( water splashes )
There you are.
What's wrong?
Something jabbed me
here in the calf.
Ooh.
O'Brien, Commander Riker's
been injured.
Lock on and bring him up.
O'BRIEN: Stand by.
Geordi, it's just...
A scratch, right.
Sorry, Commander,
we can't take any chances.
We're the first survey team
to set foot on this planet.
We don't know
what the risks are.
( beeping )
LA FORGE:
O'Brien, what's the holdup?
The transporter's detected
unidentified microbes
in Commander Riker's body.
Well, can't the biofilters
screen them out?
Apparently not, but Dr. Pulaski
has been notified.
Acknowledged.
I wasn't ready
to leave here anyway.
Here's the biofilter's
analysis of the microbes.
PULASKI:
That's not much to go on.
I can override and beam
Commander Riker aboard.
No.
I better go down and make
an evaluation there.
I hope these are
the right coordinates.
Just kidding, Doctor.
I know how much you love
the transporter.
About as much as I love
comical Transporter Chiefs.
Ready?
RIKER:
Over here, Doctor.
Fill me in.
I was walking along,
minding my own business
doing a simple
geological sweep.
Something stuck
me in the leg.
Any pain?
No, just a little
numb, that's all.
Do you know
what it was that stuck you?
We've been looking for it...
no luck.
Well, whatever it is,
it left something behind.
I'm going to take you
up to Sick Bay.
O'Brien, this
is Dr. Pulaski.
Medical override
is authorized.
Acknowledged.
This is the strangest feeling...
My whole leg just went dead.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 42976.1:
During a geological survey
on Surata IV,
Commander Riker
has become infected
by an unidentified microbe.
Number One.
Captain.
Put your foot where
it didn't belong, hmm?
Doctor said
she was getting bored.
I just thought
I'd give her a challenge.
That you did.
The Commander's nervous system
has been invaded
by an unknown
microorganism.
Not a bacteria,
not a virus,
but with the
elements of both.
There's the point of entry.
The microbes are infecting
the great sciatic nerve.
And they are multiplying
at an incredible rate.
There.
Can you remove it?
Not surgically.
The organisms
fused to the nerve,
intertwining
at the molecular level.
That's why
the transporter's biofilters
weren't able to extract it.
There's no evidence
of nerve damage,
but the organisms are
impeding nervous function.
My leg's still asleep.
Prognosis?
The infection
is spreading.
It will eventually
reach the brain.
And if it interfered
with neural activity there?
Commander Riker
could die.
How can I help?
I need to know more
about its composition.
And for that,
you need a sample.
Exactly.
Commander Data,
Mr. La Forge,
prepare to beam
down to the planet.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
I must reiterate.
It would be better
if I went alone.
Don't like my company?
Your company is
not at issue.
Your vulnerability
to the microorganism is.
I'll watch
where I step.
Besides, how do we know
this bug doesn't like androids
more than it likes humans?
Possible,
but highly unlikely.
In any event,
why risk both of us?
Because I know
exactly where
Commander Riker
was when it happened.
Mr. O'Brien, energize.
He was right over here.
I am detecting
no animal life-forms
within 50 kilometers.
However, I am reading
extensive animal remains,
mostly fossilized.
A graveyard?
I do not know.
Data.
Data, look at this.
The structure
is rhizomatous.
Hmm.
Careful.
I am always careful.
It appears to be dead.
I'm not so sure.
I'm seeing thermal variations.
Let it go for a second, Data.
Let's try something.
Maybe it likes humans
more than androids.
If you are correct,
you are placing yourself
in grave danger.
Well, I'm counting
on those great android...
reflexes of yours.
That must be what
we're looking for.
I would tend to agree.
LA FORGE:
Stand by, O'Brien.
Got it.
Energize.
Thanks, O'Brien.
Another minute and we'd
have been fossils ourselves.
Not precisely,
Geordi.
True fossilization
requires several millennia.
Here's your
sample, Captain.
Get it to Sick Bay
right away.
Report.
Captain, Commander Riker's
injury was not accidental.
Certain vines on the planet
evidently seek out
warm-blooded beings
and deliberately
infect them.
To what end?
Unknown, sir.
It is conceivable there is a
symbiotic relationship involved.
Go on.
There are numerous
animal remains in the area
leading me to hypothesize
that the vines
could be predatory.
And the vines infect animals
in order to kill them?
It is possible.
For Commander Riker's sake,
I hope my hypothesis
is in error.
Unfortunately,
Commander Data,
your hypotheses rarely are.
All negative.
There's nothing that will
cure this infection?
This microorganism
is very mysterious.
I can't even figure out
what's keeping it alive.
Or how to kill it.
Oh, I can kill it,
but not without destroying
the nerves it's inhabiting.
I know you're doing
your best, Doctor.
My best may not
be good enough.
Comfortable?
Why wouldn't I
be comfortable?
They're waiting on me
hand and foot.
I just hope they don't find
out that I'm faking it.
I wish you were faking it.
I've seen the thorn, Number One.
Yes, the doctor
showed it to me, too.
Rather harmless-looking,
isn't it?
And deadly.
I'm sorry.
Well, these things happen.
When least expected.
I'm surprised they don't
happen more often.
After all, we are
exploring the unknown.
And the unknown
can be benign...
or malevolent.
Captain, one of the things
I've learned on these voyages
and on this ship
and from you
is that most life-forms act out
of an instinct for survival
not out of malice.
It's an important lesson.
And I admire your lack
of resentment, Number One.
If you drop a hammer
on your foot,
it's hardly useful
to get mad at the hammer.
Anything?
Not yet.
What can I do?
You can get
out of my hair.
Aye, aye, Doctor.
( instrument whirring )
This bug is persistent,
I'll admit that.
But I'm not worried.
We Rikers are
ornery, too.
Matter of fact,
my great-grandfather
once got bit by a rattlesnake.
After three days
of intense pain,
the snake died.
( medical monitors
beeping quietly )
You're a very
entertaining patient.
I try.
Yes, you're making quite
an effort to be cheerful.
You of all people should know.
You feel what anyone
in your position would feel.
As the First Officer
on this ship,
I have to set an example.
Even now?
Now more than ever.
Deanna, facing death
is the ultimate test
of character.
I don't want to die,
but if I have to,
I'd like to do it
with a little pride.
And a lot of impudence.
You bet.
Dying is bad enough,
but to lose my sense of humor?
Forget it.
Imzadi...
I haven't given up yet.
( electronic beeping
intensifies )
( loud double beeps )
It's spread to
the spinal column.
It's weakening his
autonomic nervous system.
Judging by its present
rate of growth
and its infiltration pattern,
the infection will spread
to the brain within an hour.
PULASKI:
Medical Log,
Stardate 42976.3:
I can't keep
the alien infection
from spreading
to Commander Riker's brain.
Once there, it will kill him
by dampening neural impulses.
The only way
I can keep him alive
is to force the neurons
to stay active
by stimulating them directly
with electrical impulses.
Let's proceed.
Good.
Stand by with
five milligrams
of tricordrazine
in case of seizure.
Here goes.
( deep, rumbling whir begins)
( thunder cracks )
Tasha? Data?
Geordi? Worf?
Anybody?!
PULASKI:
We've stimulated
random wave activity
but the patterns
are dangerously erratic.
Hang on, Will.
Hang on.
The wave patterns are
still too irregular.
Why won't they stabilize?
Wait. I've found
the right amplitude.
There.
The patterns are steadier.
Is the stimulation preventing
the infection from taking hold?
For now.
The vertex waves
indicate a K-complex
corresponding
to an REM state.
( sighs and mutters )
He's dreaming.
( birds calling and chirping )
Hello?
( "Pop, Goes the Weasel"
being whistled out of tune )
( loses tune )
( finishes tune )
Marvelous.
How easily humans do that.
I still need much practice.
There's some puzzles
down on the...
...down on the planet
that the Captain wants answered.
He suggested I take you with me
on the away team that
I'll be leading.
I shall endeavor
to function adequately, sir.
Yes.
When the Captain
suggested you,
I looked up your record.
Yes, sir.
A wise procedure, sir, always.
Then your rank of Lieutenant
Commander is honorary?
No, sir.
Starfleet class of '78.
Honors in probability
mechanics and exobiology.
But your file says
that you're a...
A machine. Correct, sir.
Does that trouble you?
To be honest,
yes, a little.
Understood, sir.
Prejudice is very human.
Now that does trouble me.
Do you consider yourself
superior to us?
I am superior, sir,
in many ways,
but I would gladly
give it up to be human.
Nice to meet you... Pinocchio.
A joke.
Ah. Intriguing.
You're going to be an
interesting companion, Mr. Data.
What should I say?
How do I act?
What do I do?
Guinan, I need your help.
Could you step
over here a minute?
Sounds simple enough.
Now, first words out of your
mouth are the most important.
You may want to start
with something like this.
You are the most beautiful
woman in the galaxy.
But that might not work.
Yes.
Yes, it would.
You don't know how long
I've wanted to tell you that.
But you were afraid.
Yes.
Of me?
Of us. Of what we might become.
Commander...
RIKER:
Or that you might think
that was a line.
Maybe I do think
it's a line.
And you think
I'm not sincere?
I didn't say that.
There's nothing's wrong
with a line.
It's like a knock
at the door.
RIKER:
Then you're inviting me in?
GUINAN:
I'm not sending you away.
RIKER:
That's more than I expected.
Is it as much as you hoped?
To hope is to recognize
the possibility.
I had only dreams.
Dreams can
be dangerous.
Not these dreams.
I dream of a galaxy where
your eyes are the stars
and the universe
worships the night.
Careful.
Putting me
on a pedestal so high,
you may not be able
to reach me.
Then I'll learn how to fly.
You are the heart in my day
and the soul in my night.
I don't think
this is my style.
Shut up, kid.
Tell me more about my eyes.
I didn't want to leave
without saying good-bye.
I don't like good-byes.
How about "until next time"?
How about until next time.
It's been a pleasure
working with you, Commander.
The feeling is mutual...
Counselor.
I'm supposed to know
how everyone feels,
but I can't read you
right now.
Perhaps your own feelings
are getting in the way.
My job is to help others
sort out their emotions.
My own feelings
are beside the point.
Not to me.
Our feelings are what
make us all human.
Are you feeling sad?
Yes, I am.
So am I.
TROI:
He's relaxed.
Experiencing feelings of
warmth and friendship.
He's reliving memories.
It's a natural side effect
of neural stimulation.
Look at this.
The organisms' metabolism
has changed.
I wonder if the stimulation
is affecting them somehow.
I'm going to refocus
the impulse pattern
on the interpretive cortex.
To intensify
his memories?
Exactly.
We'll see if that has
any effect on the microbes.
( man laughing )
Everyone!
We've brought
the visitors.
Please, enjoy what we have.
Gentlemen...
if this is what
you call enhancement,
you've got a gift
for understatement.
What's a knockout
like you doing
in a computer-generated
gin joint like this?
Waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
You can't be serious.
Oh, yes, Will.
I've never been
more serious in my life.
PULASKI:
Something wrong?
No, it's just that Commander
Riker's emotions are...
rather passionate.
As in erotic?
Very much so.
A dream?
Is that what this is?
Is that what I am?
I know you're
a computer-generated image...
but your smell
your touch,
the way you feel,
even the things you say
and think seem so real.
Thank you.
How far can
this relationship go?
I mean, how real are you?
As real as you
need me to be.
You resist.
Don't you find me
attractive?
Yes, I find you
very attractive.
You attract me like
no man ever has.
It's not my function to
seduce or be seduced
by the leader
of another world.
It's not the reason.
No, it's not.
But will you still respect me
in the morning?
Mm, I hope so.
William, is something wrong?
What do you mean?
Do you not like girls?
Of course I do.
Oh, is there a special technique
to this foot washing?
You generally start
at the top
and work your way down.
I think I can handle that.
I was hoping you might.
The organisms responded
all right.
Their growth rate has doubled.
Then all we've done
is make things worse.
Now we know the organisms'
growth rate is related
to the memories
he's experiencing.
Or the emotions
that they produce.
Well, different mental processes
generate different chemicals.
Perhaps the organisms
are sensitive
to brain endorphins.
Then if some types of
endorphins attract them...
Others will repel them.
I'm going to change
the differential current pattern
and see what happens.
We are not going
without our shuttle crew.
I warn you.
YAR: Enough.
We have people
who need attention.
We won't hurt you,
but we must help them.
PICARD:
Number One?
The creature attacked us.
Lieutenant Yar is down.
It seems to feed
on our phaser energy.
We had no effect on it.
PICARD:
What's Lieutenant Yar's
condition?
( instrument beeping rapidly )
Doctor Crusher, report.
She's dead.
I'm losing life signs.
You must save him.
I'm sorry.
PULASKI:
The growth rate has
definitely slowed.
What is he feeling?
Can you tell?
Sadness.
Just the opposite
of before.
And it's having the opposite
effect on the infection.
Then your theory
is correct.
The organisms are sensitive
to different types
of endorphins.
And negative emotions...
Such as sadness...
Produce endorphins that inhibit
the organism's growth.
Then we found a way
to repel the infection.
Assuming we're not too late,
already.
How much time do we have?
I'm not sure.
His vital signs
are getting weaker.
I don't want to risk
another dose
of tricordrazine
unless I have to.
I must refocus
the pattern again.
We need to isolate memories
that generate
stronger negative emotions.
I know I can count on every
Klingon warrior in this crew
to serve and die
in that battle.
So I ask you again,
Commander Riker,
where are your loyalties?
I've been assigned
to serve this ship
and to obey
your orders.
And I will do exactly that.
Will you take an oath
to that effect?
I just did.
This is your Second Officer,
Lieutenant Klag.
Was there something you wanted
to say to me, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
I do not believe you.
Then I take it you challenge
my authority over you.
Correct.
And your position on this,
Captain?
I would say it is
your first command decision.
( growls softly )
Ready for your
tour, Admiral?
Quite ready,
Commander.
What's in the case?
Actually, I brought it
for Dr. Crusher,
but perhaps you would like
to see it first.
What is it?
A form of life.
It was discovered
accidentally
by a survey team
on an uncharted planet.
Why haven't we heard
anything about that?
Oh, you'll be hearing
about it shortly,
but first, there remains much
scientific study to be done.
After all, it is
a superior form of life.
Superior?
Totally.
Come, have a look.
I think I'll summon
my science officer.
It won't like
your science officer.
It does like you!
Vitamins--
they do wonders
for the body.
Riker to Security,
Guest Quarter 17. Emergency.
( menacing chuckle )
We've reduced the growth rate
even further, but not enough.
And his vital signs
are deteriorating.
But we've isolated
the specific areas to stimulate.
The feelings were primal,
survival emotions.
They must be producing
a type of endorphin
that's poisonous
to the organisms.
Well, can't you intensify
that emotion?
I can refocus the impulse
pattern even tighter,
but I don't know if
he can withstand it.
He's extremely weak.
Do we have a choice?
No.
If we don't neutralize
the infection
within half an hour,
he'll be dead.
PULASKI:
Medical Log, supplemental:
Commander Riker's condition
is still critical.
I've discovered a way
to reverse the infection's
growth rate,
but I may be too late.
He's getting weaker,
isn't he?
Respiration shallow,
heartbeat extremely irregular,
but we can't delay any longer.
You will take us to our planet
and leave us there
with our medicine
or this person dies.
Don't you see?
I have no choice.
We were sent to bring
the felicium back.
The suffering on my planet
is too great.
People are dying.
It doesn't matter whether
we're entitled to it or not.
We must have it.
Let him go.
You will take us
there now
or give us a shuttle,
but we must have
the medicine.
If you refuse,
this person will die.
I will not be coerced.
I will do it.
I will kill him.
Who are you?
( yells in pain )
Data, something's got me!
Touch him and he dies.
No! No, don't!
Enterprise.
Armus has...
enveloped Commander Riker.
I'm beaming you up.
If any of you leave now,
he dies.
And so do the survivors
of the crash.
( all gasp )
The growth rate's down to 7%.
The organisms are still
impairing his neural functions.
Respiration is erratic,
pulse grossly irregular,
blood pressure almost nil.
Tricordrazine.
Can we tighten
the pattern further?
COMPUTER:
Recognize Picard,
Jean-Luc, Captain.
Recognize Riker,
William T., Commander.
Set auto-destruct sequence.
COMPUTER:
Does the First Officer concur?
Yes, set auto-destruct
sequence... now.
COMPUTER:
Auto-destruct will detonate
in four minutes
and 59 seconds.
I am Korris.
We'll handle the
formalities later.
Right now we have to
get off this ship.
Are there any
other survivors?
No.
I believe I have found
a quicker way out of here, sir.
Check him out.
He is alive, sir,
but just barely.
Then pick up the body
and let's get out of here.
No!
I will carry him.
As you wish.
Come on, let's go!
Tasha, go to
Transporter Room 3.
I want you there
when the away team returns.
Aye, sir.
LA FORGE:
Commander, we are out of time!
This ship is blowing!
Transporter Room,
have you got a lock on us?
Too much interference.
You have to get farther away
from the engineering section.
Sir, the engineering
section is critical.
Destruction of the Batris
is imminent.
They're out of options.
Do it now!
( loud rumbling )
( explosion )
The growth rate's
almost down to zero.
That's not good enough.
We seek peaceful coexistence.
Set auto-destruct...
( alarm blaring )
Data, something's got me!
Auto-destruct...
...now.
Now.
Data, something's got me!
( sighs )
Sick Bay to Bridge.
PICARD:
Yes, Doctor.
We've eradicated the infection.
I'm on my way.
You're still here?
I could ask you
the same question.
How do you feel?
( sighs )
Beat.
You wouldn't believe
the dreams I was having.
Oh, yes, we would.
You'll be pleased to hear
that we've terminated
the infection.
Great work, Doctor.
Now, if I could
get out of here,
I'd like to get back to...
Lie still.
I still have a few
dozen tests to run.
Why?
I feel fine.
There may be some
residual memory loss.
I just want to be certain that
you still know who you are.
Of course I know who I am.
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
I'm delighted that you're
feeling better, Captain.
The Admiral and I
were worried about you.
Captain...
I do not believe
you have the authority
to promote me
to the rank of Admiral.