( mild snoring )
Riker to Ensign Crusher.
Go ahead.
Forget to set your
alarm, Wesley?
Yes, sir.
I'm very sorry.
I'll be right there.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43125.8.
We have entered a spectacular
binary star system
in the Kavis Alpha Sector
on a most critical mission
of astrophysical research.
Our eminent guest,
Dr. Paul Stubbs
will attempt to study
the decay of neutronium
expelled
at relativistic speeds
from a massive
stellar explosion
which will occur here
in a matter of hours.
Ensign,
our position?
Approaching
one million kilometers
from the neutron star, sir.
Slow to one-third
impulse power.
STUBBS:
Spectacular, isn't it,
my young friend?
Yes, sir.
Over and over again,
the intense gravitational pull
of the little neutron star
sucks up the star material
from the red giant
and it builds up
on the surface
until it explodes
every 196 years.
Like clockwork.
And it is but 18 hours away.
18 hours, seven minutes
and... ten seconds, Doctor.
The interstellar counterpart
to Earth's Old Faithful.
The only predictable burst
of energy in the universe
that can accomplish our goal.
Doctor Stubbs,
if you would like
to make one final
inspection of...
Captain, I have been inspecting
the Egg for the last 20 years.
You may lay it when ready.
Begin launch sequence.
Shuttle Bay 2, stand by
to launch... the Egg.
Standing by, Commander.
( warning Klaxon sounds )
Five minutes to launch site.
Stabilize.
The ship isn't responding, sir.
( alarm beeping )
PICARD:
Engineering.
Report, Mr. La Forge.
Checking for failure
of inertia dampeners.
Instruments
say they're working.
Captain, we're heading
straight into the path
of that stellar matter.
Shields up.
WORF:
Negative.
The shields will not respond.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
30 seconds to impact, sir.
Manual override
on shields.
WORF:
Shields are rising.
RIKER:
Reset dampeners
Mr. La Forge.
Dampeners not responding.
Unable to reset.
Reverse impulse engines.
Initiating reverse sequence...
now.
Our momentum is
still carrying us
into the path
of the stellar matter.
12 seconds to impact, sir.
Prepare for impact.
Medical personnel,
report to the Bridge.
Commander Data,
check all systems.
All systems functioning
normally, sir.
Computer,
explain control malfunction.
No control malfunction
has been recorded.
Just lay down
carefully.
There you go.
Doctor Stubbs, the Captain
asked me to tell you
that our systems
are back to normal
and we can try
another launch attempt
as soon
as you're ready.
Quite a dynamic family team--
you Crushers.
Well, it's nice
to be together again.
I was at Starfleet
Medical for a year.
I missed about...
two inches of him.
I'm not sure I'd want my mother
to be flying through
space with me.
No, I take
that back.
I am sure.
I wouldn't want her.
My mother is
a formidable
woman, too.
A woman of letters.
A great critic.
I know.
Good lord, son.
You didn't read
that unauthorized biography?
Is this all this
boy does, Doctor--
fly the ship and read?
Doesn't he ever have any fun?
Sure he does.
Actually, most of my free time
is taken up with my studies.
I'm trying to get
into Starfleet Academy.
I earn credits for the time
spent on the Enterprise
but it's just not the same.
You ready to sit up?
Well.
I am whole again.
Thank you, Doctor.
Come along, Wesley.
Let's go see if Humpty-Dumpty
is still in one piece.
( electronic humming )
( liquid splashing )
Computer, fix the food slot.
The food slot
is functioning properly.
Well, check again.
The food slot
is functioning properly.
Computer, deactivate food slot.
We're analyzing the engineering
systems data, Captain.
So far, we're showing
nothing unusual
in the computer log
for that time period.
Run a level-1 diagnostic series.
( door chimes )
Come.
I, uh... I want a computer
that's 100 percent
to expedite
Doctor Stubbs' experiment
as well as the food slots
in Sick Bay.
Picard, out.
Which seem
to be working again.
For the moment,
anyway.
What can I do
for you, Doctor?
Jean-Luc, how would you feel
if you were a 17 year old
and the only Starfleet officer
whose mother was on board?
Inhibited... I suppose.
Mmm.
But then I'm not Wesley.
And if you are...
concerned about him
I see no evidence
that there is a problem.
I know, but in a funny way,
that's exactly my point.
We talk.
We smile.
It's almost too polite.
Beverly, isn't it
just a matter of time?
I know how difficult it was
for you being away.
Tell me about him.
Well, he's becoming
a very fine officer.
He works as hard
as any member of the crew.
Riker says his studies
are on line...
No, tell me about him.
He's his father's son--
honest
trusting
strong.
Does he have many friends?
Has he ever been in love?
Um...
Jean-Luc, I'm worried.
He's come so far, so fast
and since I've been back
I don't feel...
His dependence.
Beverly, look, he's...
he's 17 years old.
What were you doing
when you were 17?
Probably getting into
more trouble than Wesley
I can assure you.
So was I.
Isn't that what 17's
supposed to be?
No cracks in the armor.
We'll do just fine.
How can you be so calm
about this?
If I were about to make
this kind of breakthrough...
I have never doubted
for a moment
that this day would come,
Wesley.
And I suspect that someday
it will come for you, as well.
I see a lot of me in you.
In my youth, they
called me a wunderkind.
Do you understand
wunderkind?
It's German, isn't it?
It means
"wonder child."
It is reserved
for those of us
who achieve
early in life.
Now the burden
is yours.
Burden?
To fulfill
your potential.
You will never
come up against
a greater adversary
than your own potential
my young friend.
( alarm sounds )
Red alert.
Return to quarters
immediately.
Still no visual contact?
That's impossible.
Mr. Worf, same magnification
50 degrees starboard.
Worf, you're
absolutely sure?
Sensors clearly indicate
the approach of a Borg vessel.
Shields up.
Shields are
not responding.
Manual override is jammed.
It's not gonna work
this time. We don't have
the shields, Captain.
Captain, they're firing
energy weapons at us.
Evasive action.
Bring her around to 275,
mark three.
Predict current vector
of Borg vessel.
Vector...
It's gone.
And so is the Borg ship.
You telling me this is
another computer glitch?
DATA:
It is conceivable
that he was viewing
a synthetically generated image,
sir.
Then our computer
was daydreaming?
PICARD:
Computer.
Identify malfunction
immediately.
COMPUTER:
Pawn to Bishop Four.
Knight to King's Rook Three.
Bishop to Queen's Bishop Four.
Knight to Knight Five.
Queen's Knight to...
Controls are
not responding, sir.
Queen to Bishop Three.
Bishop to Bishop Two.
( engines powering down )
Impulse engines are down.
Try warp engines.
Nope, sorry,
Commander.
I'd better get back
to Engineering.
Mr. La Forge
I want Lieutenant Worf
to accompany you.
Get me a full report on
the prospects of getting
our shields back.
Number One, Mr. Data, will
you join me in the conference
room as soon as possible?
It's time to discuss
the future of this mission...
if there still is one.
The fact of the matter is,
we are dealing
with the potential breakdown
of the main computer.
That's hard
to accept.
The system
automatically provides
for self-correction, Captain.
There has not been a
systems-wide technological
failure
on a Starship in 79 years.
( door opens )
Excuse me, Captain
but Dr. Stubbs
is waiting outside.
Captain, I'm sure you have
everything under control.
I'd just like to know
what's going on.
Of course, Doctor.
Sit down.
Counselor.
Commander La Forge
is attempting repairs
even as we speak.
Attempting?
That doesn't sound
particularly reassuring.
Doctor, if at all possible
we will continue
this mission as planned.
Captain,
if we miss our chance now
we don't get another
for two centuries.
There will be many questions
asked by Starfleet
if the Enterprise fails
in its duty.
Hmm. Nevertheless, my first
and foremost consideration
will be to ensure the safety
of this ship and its crew.
Ensure the safety, Captain?
Or are you really talking
about playing it safe?
My dear Doctor,
in our current position
when that star explodes,
you will get
to watch your experiment
from the inside out.
I would rather die than leave.
I don't believe you speak
for the majority of the crew.
Dr. Stubbs
I know
how much this means to you...
My dear Counselor,
no insult intended
but please turn off
your beam into my soul.
I will share
the feelings
I wish to share.
Well, if we do not leave
in time, so be it.
It's one sure way into
the record books, eh?
( door opens and closes )
His nonchalance
is studied and practiced.
Mm-hmm.
Even my sensory perception
picked that up.
He's put his entire self-worth
on the line
with this experiment.
He's telling the truth
when he says
he'd rather die than leave.
Call up the cross-section
of computer core processor 451.
I want to see elements
0200 to 0300.
Aye, sir.
In order to get some power
I had to bypass
the computer core
essentially hot-wire
the connection.
Whoa, whoa, right there.
Look at that lesion.
No wonder we're
coming apart at the seams.
It's definitely some kind
of continuing disintegration
but, from what,
I can't tell you.
And I haven't the slightest idea
how to stop it.
It's just a mechanical problem
though, right?
Increase magnification,
factor 50.
I don't know, Wes,
but looking at it...
You know, if I
didn't know any better
I'd say somebody
had climbed in there
and started
taking it apart.
Guinan.
I didn't think
anyone would be here.
I've never been
any good at being
confined to quarters--
as my husbands
will attest to.
What's that?
I'm just setting traps.
I run a clean place.
I know.
It's not that.
It's...
I'm scared, Guinan.
I think that everything
that's been going wrong
might be my fault.
You want to tell me about it?
I've been working
on my final project
for advanced genetics.
It's on nanotechnology.
I've been studying the nanites
we have in the Sick Bay
genetics supplies.
They're these little tiny robots
with gigabytes
of mechanical computer memory.
They're designed
to enter living cells
and conduct repairs.
They're supposed
to remain confined to the lab.
Are you saying
there are nanites loose?
Two of them, that's all.
I just wanted to see
how they would interact
and function in tandem.
See, in my experiment,
I had proposed a theory
that, by working together,
they could combine their skills
and increase their usefulness.
It was working.
So you made better nanites.
I was pulling an all-nighter
to collect my final data.
I fell asleep
and, when I woke up, I saw the
container had been left open.
It's just a science project.
You know, a doctor friend
once said the same thing to me.
Frankenstein was his name.
They're really harmless.
I mean, they're equipped with
only the most basic of skills.
It's almost impossible
they could be responsible.
Almost.
Dr. Crusher to Wesley Crusher.
Go ahead.
I stopped
by your quarters, Wes.
I assumed you'd be there
since you're off duty.
I know, I just had
some things to do.
Orders are orders, Mr. Crusher.
On my way.
You won't tell anybody,
will you?
I know-- I will.
If it's true.
Wes, do you think you're going
to get a good grade?
I always get an "A."
So did Doctor Frankenstein.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Our computer core
has clearly been tampered with
and yet there is no sign
of a breach of security
on board.
We have engines back
and will attempt
to complete our mission.
But without a reliable computer
Dr. Stubbs' experiment
is in serious jeopardy.
Manual restart sequence.
LA FORGE:
Manual restart successful.
Impulse engine functions
all appear normal.
Proceed.
Shuttle Bay 2,
open hangar door.
Aye, sir.
( warning Klaxon sounds )
The door did not respond.
Repeating sequence.
( "Stars and Stripes Forever"
plays loudly )
What in heaven's name...?
DATA:
It is "Stars and
Stripes Forever," sir
by John Philip Sousa
an American composer
of band music
in the early 20th century...
PICARD:
Yes, yes
I know that.
Computer,
shut off the music.
Music is on all
communications channels, sir.
Weapons, power,
communications--
we're being stripped
one system at a time.
Shut off the power
to the Bridge.
( music stops )
Commander La Forge
can you get us
out of this star system safely?
No!
Not now, Doctor.
LA FORGE:
I'll try, Captain.
I don't want to overload
the engines.
Do it gently.
But do it.
We'll circuit in auxiliary power
to the Bridge.
Somehow, we'll silence Sousa
if he decides to play an encore.
The priority is to find out
who or what is doing this.
Number One, the Bridge,
such as it is, is yours.
The Egg that
Stubbs laid.
No one will say that.
Nobody will say
anything at all, Wesley.
We will not even
be mentioned.
I could live
with failure...
Well, maybe not.
But never even to try,
to miss your one chance at bat.
Do you know baseball?
Yes, my father taught it to me
when I was young.
Once, centuries ago,
it was the beloved
national pastime
of the Americas, Wesley.
Abandoned by a society
that prized fast food
and faster games.
Lost to impatience.
But I have seen
the great players
make the great plays.
Do you recreate them
on a holodeck?
No...
in here.
With the knowledge
of statistics--
runs, hits and errors
times at bat, box scores.
Men like us do not need
holodecks, Wesley.
I have played seasons
in my mind.
It was my reward to myself
for patience.
Knowing my turn would come.
Call your shot.
Point to a star.
One great blast
and the crowd rises.
A brand-new era in astrophysics
postponed 196 years...
on account of rain.
( beeping short beeps )
( long beeps )
We have to talk.
You really look
like you could use
some rest, Wesley.
I know.
It's okay, really.
No, it's not okay.
Really.
Look, Mom
I'm just checking
some traps that I set
to see if I can find out
what's happening
to the Enterprise.
On someone's orders?
We're running out of time
for Dr. Stubbs.
You can't put everything on
your shoulders, Wesley.
Even when you're off duty,
you're on duty.
Mom, you don't understand.
You are a 17 year old.
I am also an acting officer
and I have responsibilities.
I'm beginning to think
maybe you've taken on
too many responsibilities.
Look, I have done everything
that everyone has asked
of me, and more.
And how can you know?
You haven't even been here.
I'm here now, Wesley.
Come on, I'll help you.
What are you looking for?
Wesley.
I think I've made
a horrible mistake.
DR. CRUSHER:
Nanites--
tiny machines built
from the atom up.
Designed for exposure only
to the inside of nuclei
during cellular surgeries.
Until then,
they are kept
tightly contained
in a non-functioning state.
These are not
ordinary nanites.
No, they have evolved.
Evolved? How does
a machine evolve?
It's true.
I am responsible
for this.
I allowed two
of the nanites to interact
for a school project.
I wanted to increase
their capabilities
and they escaped.
School project?
Just how far have
these things evolved?
Well...
this is a sample
of linear memory crystal
from our computer core.
It's like candy to them.
CRUSHER:
As you can see,
they're able
to mechanically
replicate themselves.
It is conceivable
that with each new generation
they enhance
their own design.
The rate of evolution
would be extraordinary.
How many generations
are we dealing with here?
Engineering, display
computer core
processor 451
element 0299.
Increase magnification
factor 1,000.
Can it be possible they
know what they're doing?
Why would they attack us?
Why does a mosquito
bite your ear?
And who cares?
The answer is simple--
call an exterminator.
Dr. Stubbs,
these nanites are now working
with a new,
collective intelligence.
Operating
together.
Teaching each other new skills.
Oh, really.
I'm sorry,
but this is nonsense.
You can't have
a civilization
of computer
chips.
They're made
in a plant
in Dakar, Senegal.
I've watched
the construction.
Then how do you explain
what we've just seen here?
It's no more mysterious
than watching a strain
of Leutscher virus
reproduce itself.
And that, at least,
is a bona fide life-form.
How many disease
germs and viruses
have you destroyed
in your time, Dr. Crusher?
Dr. Stubbs, I cannot exterminate
something that may
or may not be intelligent.
My good Captain...
There's still time.
Ensign, will you work
with Mr. Data
to try to remove
them safely?
If things get worse,
we'll use stronger measures.
Gentlemen, I need a computer
that is 100 percent
in less than eight hours.
And we still have core
reconstruction to consider.
We're trying
low gamma bursts.
We think it may slow down
their productivity.
Have you considered
a high-level charge?
High level gamma radiation
will kill them, Doctor.
I know.
I can't get the story
of Gulliver out of my head--
overpowered by Lilliputians.
How long do we have to wait?
We can continue
to bypass the part
of the computer
that's affected
but if the nanites
are spreading
through the
whole ship...
( gas hissing )
Do you smell a change in...?
( coughing )
What...?
Picard to La Forge.
We have an environmental
system malfunction
on the Bridge.
Acknowledge.
Aye, sir.
Nitrogen oxide--
toxic levels.
LA FORGE:
Working on it, Captain.
( Bridge crew coughing )
I've switched to manual control
of the air handling system.
Mr. Worf, report.
He entered
a computer access room
and sterilized one
of the processors
with gamma radiation.
DATA:
The nanites in
the upper core
are all dead, Captain.
You have no choice now.
It is a matter of survival.
Dr. Stubbs, if you were
a member of my crew, I would...
But I am not a member
of your crew, sir.
I am a representative
of the highest command
of the Federation
which has directed you
to perform my experiment.
If any man, woman or child
on this ship
is harmed as a result
of your experiment
I will have your head
before the highest command
in the Federation.
Good lord.
You are talking about machines
with a screw loose.
Simply turn them off
and be done with them.
DATA:
Dr. Stubbs
your own actions have provided
evidence to the contrary.
When you destroyed
the nanites in the core
they responded by interfering
with our life-support systems.
It is difficult to accept these
as random actions
by machines with loose screws.
In effect, you may have proven
that the nanites
do have
a collective intelligence.
Captain, the ship
is at risk.
Extermination may be
our only alternative.
Good point.
Lieutenant Worf,
I want Dr. Stubbs
confined to his quarters
until further notice.
Mr. Data, can you
find me some way
to communicate
with these things?
With intelligence, there is
the capability of language
but it will depend
on how far
their evolution
has brought them.
We could modify the
circuitry in the
universal translator
to make it capable of
communications with them.
Proceed.
( door chimes )
May I come in?
You just can't resist,
can you, Counselor?
I only want to help.
Yes, yes--
to break the shell
to get in touch
with my true feelings.
I'm only worried about
your state of mind, Doctor.
All right, Counselor.
What is it
that has you so worried?
Your single-mindedness.
Your need to have
this experiment work.
But it will.
Picard has no choice now.
He must defend
the Enterprise.
Counselor,
when this is all over
I will show you New Manhattan
on Beth Delta I, as you
have never seen it
and we will laugh
over glasses of champagne.
Your self-portrait
is so practiced, so polished.
Yes, isn't it, though?
It's stretched so tight
the tension fills this room.
And if you
finally fail
I fear it will snap.
A good try, Counselor.
But sometimes
when you reach beneath
a man's self-portrait--
as you so eloquently put it--
deep down inside,
what you find...
is nothing at all.
Lockman on first.
Dark on second.
Thompson at the plate.
Branca on the mound...
( sounds of crowded stadium )
( crack of a hit )
( crowd cheering )
( electronic zapping )
( zapping )
( equipment powering down )
( screams )
( alarm blaring )
He's coming around.
I cannot believe
this was an arbitrary attack.
Has Data made any progress
in contacting them?
Picard...
you must protect me.
Kill them.
Commander Riker
on my signal, we
will gamma irradiate
all the computer systems
throughout the Enterprise.
Let's put an end
to this conflict.
Worf, prepare to activate
gamma pulse generators.
( beeping )
Electromagnetic scanners
ready, Captain.
Captain.
I have established contact.
As we continue, Captain
they are virtually
learning the concept
of communication.
Each new generation
is making modifications.
Can we actually
talk to them, yet?
I believe it is worth
an attempt, sir.
Commander Riker,
bring Dr. Stubbs to the Bridge.
I don't think
this is a wise idea.
They have already
tried to kill me once.
One sure way into the
record books, Doctor.
DATA:
I am ready, sir.
PICARD:
Tell them that the human
who destroyed
their comrades is here
and wishes
to address them.
Captain, if I may...
And you, sir, you will
explain your error
and apologize and pray
that we can
negotiate a peace
we can all live with.
Is that clear?
Captain, if a face-to-face
negotiation
would be helpful
I would like to
volunteer myself
as a conduit.
Yourself, Data?
I can easily furnish the nanites
with a schematic design
of my neurological structure.
Entering my neural
network would require
no more than their
most basic skills.
That's what they
were designed for.
They could penetrate
the molecular fabric
of my hand-covering
into my nerve circuitry
and interface with
my verbal program.
If they have control
of a Starfleet Commander
they become
an even greater threat.
How can we be sure that we
can get them out of you?
It would be a
considerable risk, sir
but it would also represent
a gesture of trust on our part.
It could be an important step
toward peace, sir.
All right, Data,
propose it to the nanites.
The answer is yes.
They are ready, Captain.
Proceed.
You are very...
strange... looking creatures.
In our travels
we have encountered
many other creatures
perhaps even stranger-
looking than ourselves
but we try to coexist
peacefully with them.
Why did you attack us?
We misinterpreted
your actions
as an attack on us.
We were...
seeking raw materials
for our replicating process.
Yes, but you
endangered this vessel
in which we all travel.
You nearly killed
a crew member.
We meant no harm.
We were...
exploring.
I understand.
We are also explorers.
We mean no harm
to any other living creature.
I am the one responsible
for the deaths
in the computer core.
We know...
who you are.
I deeply regret
the incident.
I am a scientist on
an important mission.
Your colleagues'
exploration of
the memory core
put our mission at risk.
I was only trying
to protect
a lifetime of work
from being destroyed.
I am at your mercy.
What is "at your mercy"?
He asks
your forgiveness.
This conflict was started
by mistakes on both sides.
Let's agree to end it
here and now.
We...
agree.
I pledge we will
do everything possible
to assist your
continued survival.
Thank you.
But we have evolved
beyond any need
for your assistance.
This ship is too confining.
We require relocation.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Dr. Stubbs'
has used his influence
to have planet Kavis Alpha IV
designated the new home
of the nanite civilization.
Commander Data's neural network
has been vacated.
He has been returned to us
unharmed
and with the help
of the nanites
our computer core
has been reconstructed
in time for the experiment.
Ten seconds to
stellar blast, sir.
We're at 40 million kilometers
from the neutron star, sir.
Hold your position.
Doctor?
Do you have
any children, Guinan?
A lot.
Ever had any trouble
relating to them?
Just one.
One?
He wouldn't
listen to anybody.
Well, they all
go through that.
Not in a species
of listeners.
Did he grow out of it?
It took several
hundred years
but I managed
to bring him around.
How?
A mother shapes her child
in ways
she doesn't even realize.
Sometimes just by listening.
Cute couple.
See? Now, that is healthy
for a boy his age.
I mean that as a doctor,
not as just a mother.
Ah, it is so good to see him
having fun for a change
with an attractive
young woman
who obviously
looks at him
with extraordinary
affection.
What do you know
about this girl?