( strings being tuned )
( ensemble tuning
and warming up )
Captain, Doctor, I am
honored by your presence,
but may I suggest
you attend the second concert?
Why, Data?
Ensign Ortiz will perform
the violin part.
My rendition
will be less enjoyable.
Oh?
Although I am
technically proficient,
according
to my fellow performers,
I lack... soul.
Data, telling us
why you're going to fail
before you make the attempt
is never wise.
But is not honesty
always the preferred choice?
Excessive honesty
can be disastrous,
particularly in a commander.
Indeed?
Knowing your own
limitations
is one thing.
Advertising them to a crew
can damage your credibility
as a leader.
Because you will lose
their confidence?
And you may begin
to believe in
those limitations yourself.
( playing "Eine Kleine
Nachtmusik" by Mozart )
RIKER:
Captain, we're
receiving a message
from the Sheliak Corporate.
Origin point of the message
confirmed, sir.
It is from the Shelia
star system.
The Sheliak have not attempted
to communicate
with the Federation
for 111 years.
Why are they doing it now?
On screen.
SHELIAK:
Federation creatures,
there are humans
on the fifth planet
of Tau Cygna.
This planet was ceded
to the Corporate
in section 133, paragraph 77
of the Treaty of Armens.
We will begin settlement
of this world in four days.
Remove the humans.
What the devil...?
SHELIAK:
Federation creatures
there are humans
on the fifth planet...
Cancel message.
Tau Cygna V
is in the de Laure belt--
heavy concentrations
of hyperonic radiation.
Humans can't survive
in that environment.
Exposure to hyperonic radiation
is fatal.
Then the Sheliak are
asking us to chase ghosts.
No, Number One.
The Sheliak haven't broken
a century of silence
to send us after phantoms.
An investigation is in order.
Set course for Tau Cygna V.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain, human life-form
readings from the planet.
So the Sheliak
weren't hallucinating.
Numbers?
Impossible to get
an accurate reading.
High levels of radiation
are disrupting our sensors.
DATA:
Hyperonic radiation
also interferes
with ship's transporters.
They are now inoperable.
So are the ship's phasers.
How can humans
survive down there?
They must have found
a way to adapt.
Milan's work
with radiation sensitivity
suggests it is possible.
Perhaps with extensive
virotherapy.
Well, whoever they are,
however they survived,
we've got to get them
off the planet.
By treaty, that world still
belongs to the Sheliak.
Who are within their rights
to demand the removal
of these "trespassers."
If we don't remove them,
the Sheliak will, forcefully.
How forcefully?
The Sheliak consider humans
a lower life-form.
They would have no compunctions
about exterminating
the intruders.
Mr. Data, as you are unaffected
by hyperonic radiation,
I'd like you to go down
to the planet via shuttlecraft
and commence
evacuation procedures.
Aye, sir.
Number One...
any speculation on what
we might find down there?
My guess would be
a lone survey craft.
Maybe a dozen
or so survivors.
I think it's some sort
of shuttlecraft.
Where's it from?
Look at the markings.
It must be from the Federation.
Greetings, gentlemen.
We saw your ship.
You're the first visitor
we've had in...
The first visitor
we've ever had.
You're not human?
That is correct.
I am an android.
I am Lieutenant Commander Data
of the Federation Starship
Enterprise.
Our great-grandparents
were citizens
of the Federation.
But you don't want
to waste your time
talking to us.
You want to speak to Gosheven.
We'll take you to him.
I'm sure the Federation
will be very proud of us.
Wait until you see
all we've accomplished.
And who, precisely,
is "us"?
Don't you know?
Oh, no, I don't guess
you would.
We're descendants
of the original settlers
from the Colony Ship Artemis.
Got it.
The Artemis,
launched 92 years ago.
Destination: Septimis Minor.
When they failed to check in,
Starfleet began
an extensive search.
What carried
the Artemis
so far off course?
My local informant does
not have that information.
In the early days
on Tau Cygna V,
survival was more important
than history.
Understood.
How many are there?
15,253, sir.
15,000?
Three days,
no transporters...
we'll never get them out
in time.
Shuttles?
Loading all the Enterprise
shuttlecraft to capacity,
evacuation will take...
4 weeks, 4 days.
We need more time.
Mister Data, prepare
the colonists for an evacuation.
Aye, sir.
Get me the Sheliak.
Their home world is
quite distant, Captain.
This will take some time.
Gosheven, look what's come.
Lieutenant Commander Data
of the Starship Enterprise.
He's an android.
So he is.
Well, now that
you're here...
what do you want?
My mission is to prepare
this colony for evacuation.
Why?
Because this planet belongs
to the Sheliak.
And who is this Sheliak?
The term is plural.
The Sheliak are a nonhumanoid,
intelligent life-form,
classification R-3.
Well, this colony has
been here over 90 years.
We've never seen a Sheliak.
I'd say that makes
Tau Cygna V our planet.
The original destination of the
Artemis was Septimis Minor.
The guidance system
on the Artemis failed.
Took them off course,
far off course.
Our ancestors were lucky
to find any place to land.
And when they did, the radiation
started killing them.
The hyperonic radiation
took the lives of a third
of the colonists,
before they learned
they could adapt to it.
But our colony survived
and prospered.
Look around.
We have brought water
to the desert,
built a community.
Your accomplishments
are truly remarkable.
Yet, the Sheliak
and the Federation have a treaty
which clearly makes this planet
Sheliak domain.
Then change the treaty.
That may not
be possible.
The Sheliak wish
to colonize this planet
and are unwilling
to share it with humans.
If you are still here
when the Sheliak
colony ship arrives,
they will
eradicate you.
They'd kill all of us?
They have little regard
for human life.
Thus, the most sensible course
of action
is to prepare
a contingency plan
for the evacuation
of your people.
We're not evacuating.
Perhaps I have not
made myself clear.
Yes, you have.
Let me be equally clear.
There's going to be
no evacuation.
You've delivered
your message,
so go back to your ship.
I have work to do.
Nice catch.
Wonderful reflexes.
Sorry to test you like that,
but I was curious.
Found a new toy, have we, Ardy?
Toy?
This is the most incredible
android I've ever seen.
Have you seen many?
Actually, no.
You're the first.
Only you would get this excited
over a walking calculator.
Cybernetic intelligence
fascinates me.
Are your neural pathways
duotronic?
No, positronic.
I didn't know
that was possible.
What's your memory capacity?
How many operations
per second?
I have a million questions.
I am afraid I have
no time to answer a
million questions.
I have a mission
to accomplish.
I need to know more
about your people
and Gosheven seems
unwilling to talk
to me further.
I'm Ard'rian McKenzie.
Perhaps I can help you.
Gentlemen, we're giving you
an assignment.
The one thing
we don't want to hear
is that it's
impossible.
I need the transporters
to function
despite the hyperonic radiation.
Yeah, but that's im...
Yes, sir.
Even if we get
the Sheliak to talk,
they're not likely
to be accommodating.
Captain, when the treaty
was first negotiated,
the Federation sent
372 legal experts.
What do we have?
Thee and me.
No response.
Try them again.
Boost the signal strength.
Sheliak Corporate.
This is
the Starship Enterprise.
Respond, please.
Conversation is
neither required, nor desired.
Conversation is necessary
if we are to find a solution
to our mutual problem.
Our involvement
in Federation illegality
is not indicated.
Both parties are involved, sir.
Remove the humans
from the Tau Cygna system.
Three Earth-days remain.
Let us negotiate in good faith.
Negotiate?
To what purpose?
The treaty is signed.
There is a thriving colony
on that planet.
Rather than uproot these people,
may I offer a compromise?
Denied.
Why?
The law is paramount.
We are entitled.
This is not a law.
It is a treaty.
It is... designed to smooth
relations between races,
not to act
as a strait...
...jacket.
You really think we'll have
to leave Tau Cygna V?
The possibility
does exist.
Yet Gosheven seems unwilling
to prepare for it.
Why?
Maybe because
you're an android.
I don't think Gosheven
likes the idea
of machines
ordering him around.
I am not ordering him
to do anything.
I am merely trying
to persuade him
that his people should
prepare to evacuate.
Do you believe
my suggested course of action
should be followed?
Of course.
In spite of the fact
that I am an android?
Because of that fact.
I don't have any silly prejudice
against computers.
I like them.
Not that any computer we have
is half as sophisticated
as you are.
No, I would say not.
People can be
selfish, irrational,
stubborn, malicious--
you name it--
but computers
don't have those failings.
And you conclude because of this
that I am impartial.
Hence, you accept
my recommendations.
Yet, Gosheven
does not.
Picard to Commander Data.
Data here.
The Sheliak won't bargain.
Understood, sir.
I'm contacting Starfleet
to arrange transport.
Get those people prepared
to evacuate.
We may have to move quickly.
Aye, sir.
We must speak
to Gosheven immediately.
( sighs )
Hmm, mm, mm.
Gentlemen, how's it coming?
What the hell
is that?
Our first attempt.
Keep at it.
We need those transporters.
( water running )
You see this?
You have any idea what it is
or what it means?
It is water,
a substance composed
of two atoms
of hydrogen...
It's not water.
It's blood and it's sweat.
It's the result of 90 years
of combined effort.
This isn't a town,
it's a monument
to every man, woman, and child
who's lived and died
on Tau Cygna V.
Gosheven,
you're talking nonsense.
Am I?
My grandfather is buried
on that mountain.
He died in a rock slide
surveying the route
for this aqueduct.
This colony exists
because of his sacrifice
and the sacrifice
of thousands of others.
No, we are not leaving.
The Sheliak will not accept
humans on their planet
and they will not hesitate
to use force to remove you.
We'll not be bullied
off our land,
not by you,
and not by the Sheliak.
Stubborn and irrational.
Now what do we do?
Are his sentiments typical
of the colonists?
I hope not.
If I can convince
enough of the people
of the necessity of leaving...
Don't you mean
if we can convince?
Come.
Yes, sir.
Three weeks.
Starfleet is profuse
in its apologies,
but it will still
be three weeks...
until the arrival
of a colony transport ship
equipped with dedicated
personnel shuttles.
We can't wait three weeks.
Then the Sheliak must agree
to extend our deadline.
If they plan to settle
Tau Cygna V
two days from now...
One of their ships
must already be en route.
We're going to intercept
that ship.
The Sheliak may interpret that
as a hostile act.
It's a risk
we have to take.
The Enterprise is going
to intercept
the Sheliak colony ship.
Now your job...
Well, you know what your job is.
DATA:
Commander,
in human parlance,
I do not believe
I can get the job done.
My training has prepared me
for starship command duties.
As a cultural contact,
I am proving to be
less than exemplary.
What's the situation?
Their leader refuses my counsel.
He denies the logic
of my arguments
and speaks of structures
they have built.
Then try something else.
I have, sir.
In the last three hours
and eight minutes,
I have spoken with 56 colonists.
Ten of those refused to believe
a threat exists.
22 favor staying
and fighting the Sheliak.
16 prefer negotiation
or some sort
of passive resistance.
Only eight were willing
to consider evacuation
and of those eight...
Data, I can't help you.
I don't know these people.
I haven't talked to them.
You have.
Use that fancy positronic brain
of yours
and carry out your mission.
Sir, if I do not succeed,
how violent is the Sheliak
reaction likely to be?
The treaty is the only thing
that prevented them
from eradicating the colony
the moment they discovered it.
Ah.
"Ah" is right, Data.
The lives of 15,000 people
are riding on you.
You'd better get innovative.
Riker out.
Data?
We're having an effect.
So many people are asking
questions about the Sheliak
that Gosheven has called
a public meeting.
Is there any indication
that Gosheven
has changed his position?
No, but a meeting
will give you a chance
to present your
recommendations.
So far, my attempts
at persuasion
have been ineffective.
Why did you do that?
You appeared to need it.
Among humans, a kiss usually
serves to seal a friendship
or indicate support,
attraction, affection.
In this context, I must assume
that your intention
was to express support.
You really don't understand
human behavior, do you?
That is something
of an understatement.
Well, sometimes
I don't either.
Androids are a lot
more rational.
Thus far, that quality
has not helped me
to accomplish my mission.
A rational argument
isn't always enough.
Maybe, to be more persuasive,
you need to use a little
reverse psychology.
Ah, elicit a desired behavior
by advocating its opposite.
That implies deception,
does it not?
A little, but if it helps
us get our point across...
Perhaps this is a situation
where excessive honesty
can be detrimental.
Now, how are
we progressing,
Mr. La Forge?
About like you'd expect, sir.
Splendid,
splendid.
Carry on.
WESLEY:
He wants the impossible.
LA FORGE:
That's the short definition
of "captain."
GOSHEVEN:
You've all heard of the android
Starfleet has sent here
and you've been discussing
why he's come.
I called this meeting
to replace misinformation
with cold, hard fact.
I wish to speak.
No, leave now.
Do you consider
your position so weak
that it cannot
withstand a debate?
Let him speak.
( crowd murmuring )
You all know
of the Sheliak threat.
Starfleet wishes to evacuate you
for your own protection.
Yet Gosheven
has decided otherwise.
That is his right
and I will not waste time
trying to reverse that decision.
I admire your conviction
in the face of certain defeat.
Though doomed,
your effort will be valiant
and when you die,
you will die
for land and for honor.
Your children will understand
that they are dying
for a worthy cause.
Long after the battle is over,
their courage
will be remembered and extolled.
Remembered by who?
Yes, that is true.
There will be no one left alive
to remember.
( clapping )
A valiant try, android.
But what a low opinion
you must have of us.
I was simply attempting
to describe
your inevitable destruction
in a manner that would have
an emotional effect.
And he describes it
pretty damn well.
Are you ready to follow
this machine?
Give up without a fight?
He says we're going to lose,
but I think that's just
his cowardice talking.
MAN:
What if he's right
and you're wrong?
Shouldn't we consider
that possibility?
This colony exists
because generations
gave their lives for it.
Many died
before we found a way
to adapt to the radiation
and many more died
bringing water to this desert.
My grandfather...
Is buried on that mountain.
Well, who'll be left
to bury you?
Have you considered
what this evacuation means?
Everything we have, we abandon.
Everything that we have built
turns to dust.
Everything that we have
accomplished means nothing.
Well, I say no.
You elected me your leader.
Follow me now.
I don't think our chances
are as hopeless as he says,
and I'm willing to stake
our lives on it.
Any objections?
Good, because here we stand.
Aye.
We stand with you, Gosheven.
Then here you die.
Mr. Data, I just
want you to know
that Gosheven doesn't
speak for all of us.
I see no reason
to die needlessly.
And you?
I'm not sure.
Gosheven's done
well for us,
but I'd like to
hear more of what
you have to say.
There are many others
that feel the same way,
but they're very uneasy
about confronting Gosheven.
Get them together
and we'll meet at my house.
In our dealings
with other non-humanoid races,
there has always been
some point of reference.
Not so with the Sheliak.
But we must have
something in common.
We communicate.
Barely.
They have learned several
Federation languages,
but theirs continues
to elude us.
Telepaths?
Attempted and failed.
Actually, the fact
that any alien race
communicates with another
is quite remarkable.
We are stranded on a planet.
We have no language in common,
but I want to teach you mine.
S'smarith.
What did I just say?
Cup?
Glass?
Are you sure?
I may have meant "liquid,"
"clear," "brown," "hot."
We conceptualize the universe
in relatively the same way.
Point taken.
In your talks, you must be
extremely accurate.
The treaty is 500,000 words.
The length was to accommodate
the Sheliak.
They consider our language
irrational
and demanded this level
of complexity
to avoid any future
misunderstandings.
RIKER:
Captain, we have the vessel
carrying the Sheliak colonists
on visual.
On my way.
So. It begins.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Starship Enterprise.
Your purpose, Enterprise?
We desire face-to-face
negotiations
to settle the crisis
on Tau Cygna V.
Meaningless.
We are entitled to consultation
under paragraph 653,
subparagraph nine.
Granted.
Was that
an invitation?
I am taking it as such.
Counselor.
You have the Bridge, Number One.
Helm, maintain
relative position.
Mr. Worf, tell Transporter
Room 2 to stand by.
Aye, sir.
And once the Federation
resettles us,
we'll be left alone?
If you so desire.
We do.
We like to do things
on our own.
The Federation will
offer as little
or as much help
as you dictate.
Kentor, are you with us?
Yes. The question is,
how do we convince Gosheven?
Well, why do we need to?
Because he's respected.
Most people will do
what he says.
They respect you, too.
If you take a stand,
they'll fall in line.
I don't know.
Gosheven's got
a lot of supporters.
GOSHEVEN:
Don't forget that, Kentor.
I'm disappointed.
I thought we'd settled this.
Apparently, that
is not correct.
Still stirring up trouble?
Since when is talk trouble?
It's over.
Don't you get it?
You had your say.
You lost.
I appear to be reversing
that defeat.
No, you're not.
You're just stubborn.
Well, let me tell you something.
So am I.
Damn you, Gosheven.
You killed him.
I've killed no one.
I merely shut down a machine.
That's it, everyone.
It's time to go home.
You'll see that I'm right.
Advance and speak.
Director, we will comply
with your request
to remove the colony
from Tau Cygna V,
but we need time.
The given time has elapsed.
We carry the membership
and we will proceed
with their debarkation.
The temporary presence
of these humans
should not interfere
with your plans.
Unacceptable.
You must remove the creatures.
I'm trying, but
the needed ship
will not be available
for three weeks.
Then you are in violation.
I have admitted that.
I am only asking for
a little flexibility.
Section 501, paragraph 716,
subparagraph five.
"Unwanted life-forms
inhabiting H-Class worlds
may be removed at the discretion
of the Sheliak Corporate."
We will remove them,
but you must grant us
the time we require.
You need time, Picard,
of the Enterprise?
We will save you time.
We will eradicate
the human infestation.
They are not vermin.
They are citizens
of the Federation.
I will not permit this outrage!
Intelligent converse
is impossible.
You do not discuss.
You gibber.
Between intelligent
species of good will...
I take it the Sheliak
just hung up on us again.
I was afraid
your neural pathways
were scrambled beyond repair.
I am equipped with
diagnostic circuits
and am able to correct
many malfunctions.
I'm not surprised
at Gosheven's behavior,
but Kentor and the others
they said they were with us.
I guess words
don't mean very much.
Perhaps that is a part
of our difficulty.
Words are all
we have been using.
Humans seem to take
much stronger notice of actions.
I require a phaser.
What's a phaser?
A type of weapon.
Unfortunately,
it does not function
in the presence
of hyperonic radiation.
I will have to be innovative.
Hyperonic radiation
randomizes phaser beams,
but I believe I can improvise
a servocircuit
which will compensate
by continuously
recollimating the output.
You're using your own
neural subprocessors
to build a smarter phaser.
Essentially correct.
Get word to Gosheven.
Tell him I am coming
to the pumping station.
Tell him I am going
to destroy the aqueduct.
He'll try to stop you.
I sincerely hope so.
Go to yellow alert.
Shields up.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Riker, put us nose-to-nose
with the Sheliak vessel.
Any move she makes,
match it.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, hailing frequency.
Open.
They're not responding.
They don't have to answer.
They just have to listen.
Sheliak vessel...
you will have to get past me
to get at the colony
on Tau Cygna V.
No response.
Close channel.
And get me that treaty.
They've been beating us over
the head with it for three days.
Let's see if we can't
find something in it
that we can turn
to our own advantage.
( yells )
DATA:
Stop.
That was the "stun" setting.
This is not.
( all gasping )
I can reduce
this pumping station
to a pile of debris.
But I trust my point is clear.
I am but one android
with a single weapon.
There are hundreds of Sheliak
on the way
and their weapons
are far more powerful.
They may not
offer you a target.
They can obliterate you
from orbit.
You will die, never having
seen the faces of your killers.
The choice is yours.
There are other places,
other challenges.
( people agreeing )
( groaning )
I really was willing
to stay here and die for this.
I know that.
This is just a thing and
things can be replaced.
Lives cannot.
WORF:
This is hopeless.
Fighting would
be preferable.
That's it.
I don't
follow you, sir.
Mr. Worf, get me
the Sheliak.
Yes, sir.
Coming through, sir.
PICARD:
Pursuant to paragraph 1290,
I hereby formally request
third party arbitration
of our dispute.
You have the right.
Furthermore,
pursuant to subsection D-3,
I name the Grisellas
to arbitrate.
Grisellas?
Unfortunately,
they are currently
in their hibernation cycle.
However, they will awaken
in six months,
at which time we can get
this matter settled.
Now, do you want to wait
or give me my three weeks?
Absurd.
We carry the membership.
We can brook no delay.
Then I hereby declare
this treaty in abeyance.
Wait, negotiation
is permissible...
You enjoyed that.
You're damned right.
( com beeping )
Captain, they
are hailing us.
( beeping continues )
Sir?
On screen.
You may have your three weeks,
Picard, of the Enterprise.
Thank you.
Captain, we can do it.
We can modify
the transporters.
Excellent.
It'll take 15 years
and a research
team of 100...
Mr. La Forge,
I believe we will postpone.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant Commander Data
to Enterprise.
I am preparing to leave
Tau Cygna V
and await
rendezvous instructions.
WORF:
Acknowledged. Stand by.
Hi.
The evacuation plan
is going well.
When the ship arrives,
we'll be ready to leave.
You succeeded.
I could not have succeeded
without your support
and insight.
I am grateful
for your assistance.
Good.
Then you won't forget me.
I am incapable of forgetting.
I will remember every detail
of my visit here
with perfect clarity.
But nothing more?
I do not understand.
I guess what I really want
to know is...
do you have
any feelings for me?
I have no feelings of any kind.
No, of course you don't.
What was that for?
You appeared to need it.
So you saw that I was unhappy
and did what you concluded
would make me feel better?
Rational to the last.
Bye.
( door chimes )
Come.
( classical music playing )
Welcome home, Mr. Data.
Well done.
Thank you, sir.
( music continues )
The good doctor was kind
enough to provide me
with a recording
of your concert.
Your performance
shows... feeling.
As I have recently
reminded others, sir
I have no feeling.
That's hard to believe.
Your playing is
quite beautiful.
Strictly speaking, sir,
it is not my playing.
It is a precise imitation
of the techniques
of Jascha Heifetz
and Trenka Bron-ken.
Is there nothing of Data
in what I'm hearing?
You see, you chose
the violinists.
Heifetz and Bron-ken have
radically different styles,
different techniques,
and yet you combine them
successfully.
I suppose I have learned
to be creative, sir...
when necessary.
Mr. Data, I look forward
to your next concert.