Captain's Log,
Stardate 43152.4.
We are cautiously entering
the Delta Rana star system
three days after receiving
a distress call
from the Federation colony
on its fourth planet.
The garbled transmission
reported the colony
under attack
from an unidentified
spacecraft.
Our mission is one of rescue
and if necessary, confrontation
with a hostile force.
Shields up,
maximum strength.
Shields up.
Sensors do not indicate
the presence of any
armed space vehicles
operating within
the Rana system.
They could be cloaked
or otherwise shielded.
Mr. Crusher, bring us in
well clear of
the planet's three moons.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Captain, we
are not receiving
Rana IV's call sign.
Open a frequency
to colony operations.
( communications beep )
No response.
Rana IV is
emissions quiet.
Captain, there are 11,000
inhabitants in this colony.
At this range,
I should be sensing something.
I'm not.
Mr. Data, put the planet
on the main viewer.
PICARD:
Magnify.
My God.
Helm, put us
in high equatorial orbit.
Scan for survivors.
Sensors are scanning
90 degrees of longitude
as we orbit.
I am detecting no
bodies of water
no vegetation, no
artificial structures.
Life-form readings are negative.
Could the colonists
have escaped?
DATA:
That is highly unlikely.
Rana IV possessed
no interstellar spacecraft.
Who would cause devastation
on that order?
WESLEY:
Hold it.
Captain, I've got
something here.
37 degrees north
and 62 degrees east.
It's a structure.
Life?
Two life-forms...
possibly human.
Put that area on
the main viewer
and magnify.
DATA:
The structure is located
at the center
of the vegetation, sir.
An entire planet
obliterated
except for a few acres
of trees and grass
and one building?
It must be
some kind of illusion.
DATA:
Negative.
It is as you see it.
Number One, I think
you had better see
who's at home.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
If they're the only survivors
of a nuclear holocaust
they can't be
in very good shape.
I understand.
Counselor?
What I sense
of them is human.
And something else?
It's difficult
to explain.
I feel
there's something different
about these two people.
I'm sorry.
I can't be clearer
than that.
( door opens )
We're ready.
Good luck, Number One.
Energize.
Geordi, what can
you tell me?
The house is a typical
settlement structure
with adaptations.
Thermal properties all seem
to conform to known materials.
DATA:
If there are
any indicators
as to why
this particular area
has remained intact,
I cannot detect them.
Worf, the interior
of the house.
There is one individual
located at the south
end of the house
the other toward
the north.
There is a weapon--
a low-yield phaser,
nonfunctional
in proximity to the
front room individual.
I guess a frontal assault
is unwarranted.
Stay here.
I think I'll try
an old-fashioned
knock on the door.
Commander, wait!
There's something concealed
under the surface...
( yells )
MAN:
What are you doing there?
This is private property.
Who are you people?
I'm Commander William Riker
of the USS Enterprise
crew members.
May I come down
and approach you?
You leave him right
where he is.
Should I incapacitate
him, Commander?
No.
We're a rescue party.
We picked up
your colony's distress call
and we came
as fast as we could.
Kevin.
Kevin, what are
you doing?
Can't you see they're
here to help us?
Can't you see
they're human?
Go back in the house, Rishon.
This could be
some kind of a trick.
We had almost given up hope.
We were afraid maybe the whole
Federation had been attacked.
What about the colony?
Do you know
of any other survivors?
It's been days since we've seen
or heard from anybody.
No, don't. Don't tell me
that we're the only ones.
They came in a
spaceship so big
you could see
it in orbit.
They took our world
apart piece by piece.
Who?
We don't know.
We never saw
their faces.
You don't know
where they came from
where they are now?
I guess they've
gone away.
( gasping )
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm only performing
a physical.
Could I have your names, please,
just for the record.
I'm Rishon Uxbridge
and this is my husband Kevin.
DATA:
Botanists
originally from
the aquatic city
New Martim Vaz,
in Earth's Atlantic Ocean
residents of the Rana IV colony
for five years.
You, madam,
are 82 years of age
and a composer
of Tao-classical music.
You, sir,
are 85 years of age
and a specialist
in symbiotic plant life.
You have been married
for 53 years.
I memorized the colony register
on the way to Rana IV
in the event that such
information would be needed.
Is something wrong?
With your permission
I'd like to look
inside of the house.
Why? What could interest you
in there?
Mr. Uxbridge, as
far as we've been
able to determine
you and your wife
and this house
are all that
survived that attack.
Now that's either
a bizarre coincidence
or by design
and I don't favor
the coincidence theory.
Are you saying that we were
kept alive intentionally?
Yes.
I don't understand.
You don't think Rishon
and I did something
that merits survival, do you?
I mean, betrayed the others?
I'm not accusing you
of anything, Mr. Uxbridge.
The attacking force spared
you for some reason.
We'd like to know why.
Now, may I go inside?
I'll make everyone
a nice cup of tea.
We have lovely tea
here on Rana.
It grows wild
almost everywhere...
WORF:
Sir.
May I say your
attempt to hold the
away team at bay
with a nonfunctioning
weapon was an act
of unmitigated gall.
Didn't fool you, huh?
I admire gall.
Go ahead.
Pick it up.
( waltz playing )
It's a music box.
It's been in my family
for generations.
( waltz continues )
( waltz continues faintly )
There's nothing unusual
about this house
except the fact
that it's here.
What about them?
They are in reasonably
good health.
Both show signs
of stress--
which is understandable
considering what
they've been through.
Somehow they're different.
Let's get back to the ship.
We'll take them with us.
Excuse me, Mrs. Uxbridge
but we've got to return
to our ship now.
But I haven't
finished fixing
your tea, Commander.
I'm sorry,
but we've finished here.
Now, I can allow time
for you and Kevin to pack.
What do you mean, "pack"?
You're not thinking of taking us
with you, are you?
Surely you don't want
to remain here.
How could you take care
of yourselves?
Kevin, I can't
leave my home.
Don't let them
do this to us.
No one's going
to make us leave.
RIKER:
You'll be protected
on our ship.
You could still be
in danger here on Rana.
Commander, we appreciate
your concern
but we're not going anywhere.
We'll manage.
We always have.
All right, I can't make you
come with us.
Are you familiar
with one of these?
We'll be in the system
for the next several days,
at least.
If you reconsider,
please contact us.
We'll be fine,
Commander.
We have each other.
Are they collaborators?
Did they provide
the colony's assailants
with something that abetted
the total destruction
of Rana IV
in order to protect
their own lives?
What could two botanists
in their 80s possess
that could possibly aid
whoever attacked the planet?
We don't know what
their enemy needed, Doctor.
Love, fear, hope.
( hears the waltz playing )
LA FORGE:
Maybe they're being
held hostage in some fashion.
CRUSHER:
No, nothing in
the tricorder readings
indicated they were under
that kind of stress.
PICARD:
Counselor?
Counselor Troi?
I'm sorry, um...
I don't sense them
well enough.
Number One,
you say the couple
is incapable
of sustaining themselves?
There's a fusion
reactor in the house
good for another
five years of power
but their water
table is tainted...
( hears the waltz playing )
...and they have nothing
to feed themselves
except for a small garden.
And they won't come
to the ship?
They were adamant about it.
Well, we'll do
what we can for them
but in the meantime
I want them kept
under surveillance.
I'm sorry,
I'm not feeling very well.
I'd like to go to my quarters.
By all means.
Is there anything I can do?
Captain, a search
of the Ranian system
has determined
that the hostile force
that attacked this planet
is no longer present.
I remember a Starfleet admiral
once saying the same thing
about some renegade Andorians
in the Triangular system.
It turns out that they had
dismantled their ship
and hidden it.
Those Andorians did
not have to contend
with someone
of my thoroughness.
I will stake
my reputation.
( door opens and closes )
( hears waltz playing )
Don't listen.
Think of something else.
( waltz continues playing )
Stop! Please stop!
( door chimes )
( music stops )
Yes?
I was concerned.
I came to see
if I could be of any help.
I'm fine.
There's nothing wrong.
I'm just tired, that's all.
Now, I may not have your gifts
at reading emotions, Counselor
but I can tell
when someone is in pain
and hiding it.
It's so silly.
I hear music in my mind--
music that won't stop.
Perhaps it's a symptom
of fatigue.
We've all been inflicted,
one time or another
with that melody
that won't go away.
No. It's deeper than that.
The song doesn't stop
for an instant.
It plays in perfect clarity
from beginning to end,
over and over again.
I don't even
know what song it is.
I never heard it before.
When did this start?
A few hours ago, while the away
team was on the surface.
I was trying to...
I was thinking
of Rishon and Kevin.
Rishon and Kevin, and...?
I can't explain it,
Captain.
They're elusive.
They're...
I'm... I'm sorry.
Well, try and rest.
Take the necessary sleep
inducements if you have to.
( alarm sounds )
Data, give us a visual.
Magnification factor 50.
WESLEY:
Look at the size of that.
Now where did
that come from?
Apparently, it was riding
a Lagrange point
hiding behind Rana IV's
furthest moon.
Our vehicle
classification index
can put no identity to it.
Its design
is completely foreign.
RIKER:
But that's our boy.
Approximately five times
our mass
and carrying enough armament
to pulverize a planet.
Lieutenant?
I, uh... cannot
explain this, Captain.
RIKER:
It's heading for the planet.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
Mr. Data, ask them
to identify themselves
and match our orbit.
They've received
the message, Captain
but are ignoring it.
Maximum shields. Ready
all weapon systems.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
It's assuming an attack posture.
Don't be surprised if...
The vessel is firing
jacketed streams
of positrons and antiprotons.
Equivalent firepower:
40 megawatts.
Shields are holding.
Again, 40 megawatts.
No damage.
Well, if that's the best
they can do
this should last
about five minutes.
Mr. Worf, let's raise
our voice a little.
Fire phasers.
Just a warning shot.
Mr. Data, invite
them to stand to.
The vessel
has assumed a position
outside of the Rana system
and it is rapidly
increasing velocity.
Helm, initiate pursuit.
Aye, sir.
The vessel has reached warp two
and continues on
a steady acceleration curve.
We're not getting
any closer, Commander.
Give us a superior curve,
Mr. Crusher.
Warp three, warp four...
The warship continues to match
our acceleration curve
simultaneously point per point.
Warp 4.5, warp five, warp 5.5...
Riker to La Forge
give us everything you can
to close that gap, Geordi.
Yes, sir. I'll get you
to 9.37 in 15 seconds.
Warp 8.75, warp nine.
The warship
continues
to match our
acceleration
curve perfectly.
Number One, I have
the distinct impression
that we are
being toyed with.
Take us back to Rana IV.
Back?
We have unfinished
business there.
I need to have a talk
with those two people.
You have the Bridge.
Reduce speed.
Bring us around
on a return course.
This one's getting away.
Good afternoon.
I'm sorry
if I startled you.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard,
Captain of the Enterprise.
I have brought you something
you will need
if you're going
to stay on Rana IV.
It's a matter replicator.
It has limited
capabilities, but...
Thank you, but we have
no use for such a thing.
It will provide you
with clothing, food
and clean water.
Lieutenant Worf will demonstrate
its operation.
We don't need it.
Kevin, you know we do.
Thank you, Captain.
Kevin and I were about to have
afternoon tea.
You and Mr. Worf must join us.
I'd like that very much.
Rishon, they only
want to spy on us
like this morning.
Kevin Uxbridge
I have never turned anyone
away from this house
and I'm not going
to start now.
Captain?
Thank you.
Stop! Stop!
( hears waltz playing )
Please, I'll do anything.
Make it stop.
( agonized groaning )
Please.
Hey, I'm here to help.
It's so loud.
It's getting louder.
Please, I can't stand it.
Make it stop.
Move her to the bed.
This will help you relax.
( music continues )
I hear it.
It's still there.
It's so loud.
Take her to Sick Bay.
No, I want to stay
in my quarters.
I can get you to sleep.
I don't want to sleep.
The music will
only follow me.
I can induce delta sleep.
Block out even
your deepest dreams.
It's not a dream.
It's real.
Kevin and I first met each other
on a ship at sea.
He was a starving student
with this threadbare suit
and mismatched shoes.
I was traveling
with my parents
who did not like
the way that he
kept hanging around.
Two hours after I met him,
I asked him to marry me
and he knew I was serious.
I don't think that he's ever
recovered from that day.
Well, what do you think,
Mr. Worf?
Good tea...
nice house.
Why did you leave the Earth
and come to a brand-new planet
when you did?
You mean at our age?
Well, we thought
that it might make us
fall in love all over again.
It worked.
It must have been terrible
when the colony
was fighting for its life.
Yes, it was.
Fires lit the sky.
There was thunder, this...
this unbelievable thunder.
The ground
never stopped shaking.
And yet...
you survived.
We don't know
why we survived
and the others didn't.
I've tried to put
some purpose to it
but I can't.
I was wondering, Captain
when you and your ship
would be leaving.
I don't have
an answer for that.
A few hours ago,
we encountered a warship.
Possibly the one
that attacked you.
We forced it to leave the system
but we were not able
to affect it otherwise.
It could return.
Kevin, you said
it had gone away.
I guess I was wrong.
Now, don't worry.
It didn't hurt us before.
It won't hurt us now.
Do you know that
for a fact, Kevin?
No, but I don't enjoy seeing
my wife frightened.
We've told you time and again
we don't know why
we were spared.
But there had to be some reason.
In some way you were "different"
from the other colonists.
Your geographical location,
your philosophical beliefs...
the color of your eyes.
Some way, you were set apart
from them.
There was a difference.
I am a man
of special conscience.
While the others did
what they could
I chose not to fight.
Well, that is
your protected right.
But I can assure you
the attacking ship
had no way
of realizing this.
I expected to die
like all the others.
There's no reason
for you and your ship
to remain, Captain.
We can manage without you.
Kevin grieved for the others,
Captain, but he did nothing.
He is a very
gentle man.
You must understand that.
What about you, Rishon?
Is that how you feel?
I wanted to fight,
but I stayed with my husband.
Well, Captain, uh, thank you
again for the replicator.
I better clean up now.
Before we leave,
I ask you one more time
to come to the ship.
For your own safety.
Captain, I am frightened, but...
I can't leave Rana,
even if it means my life.
I don't understand it.
I've inhibited almost all
the activity of the neocortex
and she continues to behave
as if she's hearing the music.
We're going to have
to shield her
from all outside stimuli
by inducing coma.
( alarm sounds )
I have a positive
identification, Commander.
It is the vessel
that attacked us earlier.
It is reentering the system
at high velocity
and is approaching Rana IV.
Give us a tight visual, Data.
RIKER:
Is it my imagination
or does it look
a lot meaner this time?
Shields up,
weapons ready.
Our friend is back.
I'm not surprised.
Mr. Worf, open
a hailing frequency.
Warn the vessel
to stay clear
of the planet.
Aye, sir.
But they are already
within firing range.
WORF:
Shields are down.
Captain...
they hit us with 400 gigawatts
of particle energy.
Damage?
Superficial.
But I'm having trouble
reassembling the shields.
Shields down.
There's thermal damage
to the hull.
The warship is capable
of striking us
with far more
powerful bursts.
They're maneuvering
to come
between the Enterprise
and Rana IV.
Number One, we have been
exemplary in our patience.
Lieutenant Worf,
fire phasers on full
with a simultaneous
spread of torpedoes.
The vessel appears undamaged,
sir.
Its defenses
are apparently
able to absorb
incoming matter
and energy.
Commence rapid fire
with all weapons on full.
Shields down.
Internal damage.
Weapon systems control
has been lost.
Riker to Sick Bay.
Medical assistance
to the Bridge.
On our way, Commander.
Mr. Crusher, move the
Enterprise out of range
of the attacking vessel.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Mr. Worf?
The vessel has
terminated its pursuit.
It is assuming
an orbit
around Rana IV.
Kevin and Rishon?
We can't help them.
But it's my guess that
they're in no danger.
Can you help her?
I've done
everything I can.
I don't understand the
nature of this music
she says she's hearing,
or where it's coming from.
Could it be telepathic?
Yes, but I'm
not the expert
in determining that.
They're blocking
her sensitivity.
They're stopping her
from seeing
the truth.
CRUSHER:
Who's stopping her?
Kevin and Rishon.
What?
They wanted us
to leave Rana IV
and that's exactly
what we're doing.
Picard to Bridge.
RIKER:
Yes, Captain?
Number One, I want you
to maintain this course
for another hour
and then turn
the Enterprise around
and take her back to Rana IV.
We still won't have our shields
restored by then.
Take her back, Number One
and this time, nothing
is going to lure us away.
Sir, sensors indicate
no spacecraft
in the vicinity
of Rana IV, but, Captain...
Forget your previous
error, Mr. Worf.
There is no way
you could have
prevented it.
Captain, the Uxbridge house is
coming into transporter range.
Mr. Worf, will you
accompany me to the
Transporter Room?
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Captain, I think
you should reconsider.
That warship has come
after us twice.
It could come back.
I disagree, Number One.
I don't think it
knows we're here.
I think that
it believes
that it has run
us off for good.
However, that will
all change once
I'm back on board.
Sir?
It's protecting
Kevin and Rishon.
It responds to their wishes
indirectly or directly,
I'm not sure
but that's what I'm
going to put to the test.
( waltz playing )
Celebrating?
What are you
doing here?
What do you want?
This is the second time
that you have
shown surprise
at my appearance.
The first time was
understandable, but now?
Unless it is because
you never expected
to see me again.
Why do you keep interfering
with our lives, Captain?
It is not my intention
to interfere
only to help you and Rishon.
Then, please, leave us alone.
I promise you
that when I leave this house
I will never
set foot in it again
but the Enterprise will remain
in orbit over the planet.
Why?
PICARD:
To protect you.
That's not necessary.
I thought you understood.
It is necessary.
You're in grave danger.
The warship has returned.
Kevin...
He's lying, Rishon.
We have fought
a pitched battle
with it and lost.
Many of my crew
have been injured
including a woman whose mind
is being slowly destroyed
by telepathic manipulation.
No. Please, no.
This is a form
of intimidation.
I have my rights.
Your rights?
What about Rishon?
Is she in favor
of being left here?
Come to the Enterprise.
Let me take you
where you'll be safe.
No.
I can't leave Kevin.
I'm staying.
She's safe here with me
in this house.
Why are you safe?
Why is this house a sanctuary?
Does it have to do with you?
With your refusal to fight?
Tell me this.
If Rishon were in danger,
would you kill to save her life?
No, not for her, not for anyone.
I will not kill.
Please, stop hurting him.
Captain, leave our house.
It is my sworn duty
to protect you.
The Enterprise will remain
in orbit around Rana IV
as long as the two of you
are alive.
Number One, an update, please?
Little change, Captain.
Our shields are
still inoperable.
We have partial control
of our weapons.
And I've doubled
the repair crews.
The warship is
approaching
from high orbit.
It is very close.
300,000 kilometers distant.
How is that possible?
Something wrong
with the sensors?
That's no concern,
Number One.
It's here and it's
precisely on schedule.
The vessel
has altered it's course
to a direct intercept
with the Enterprise.
Worf, arm phasers
and photon torpedoes.
Prepare to fire.
Belay those orders,
Mr. Worf.
The vessel is now
within 20,000 kilometers
of the Enterprise
and closing.
Let it come.
Activate the main viewer.
Evasive action, sir?
The Enterprise will hold
its position, Mr. Worf.
Weapons, sir?
On my orders,
not before.
The vessel is entering a
low orbit around Rana IV.
It appears to be
preparing to fire
at the planet, Captain.
Understood.
My calculations indicate
that its target is the house
of Kevin and Rishon Uxbridge.
There will be no interference
from us, Mr. Data.
The house has been obliterated.
Scan for survivors.
There are no survivors.
Mr. Worf...
prepare a photon torpedo.
Fire at the enemy vessel
when ready.
Aye, sir.
Number One, what reason
does the Enterprise have
for remaining at Rana?
The unknown vessel
has been destroyed.
The Uxbridges
have been destroyed.
There's no reason for the
Enterprise to remain.
Good.
Helm, move us
into higher orbit
so that we may
keep the surface
of the planet
under surveillance.
Aye, sir, but, Captain...
what are we watching for?
Anything, everything.
I'll be in my ready
room if I'm needed.
That will be
all for now.
( door chimes )
Come.
May I speak
with you, Captain?
It's my pleasure,
Number One.
We've been observing
this planet
very carefully
for three hours.
We've seen nothing.
I have the feeling
you're waiting for
something to happen.
Your Captain is acting
on an assumption, Will
and I'm not sure
what the result will be
or even that my assumption
is correct.
We found two people alive
in a house
on a devastated planet
but there was
only one survivor
of the war on Rana IV.
Why is it we maintain watch
on a planet
that is now totally dead?
( console beeping )
Bridge to Captain Picard.
You'd better come see this.
Captain, Commander,
the house is back.
Trees, grass,
everything.
Happened right
in front of us.
Mr. Worf, do you
see any survivors?
I detect two life-forms
inside the house.
It appears Kevin and Rishon
were not destroyed.
Helm, take us within
transporter range.
We're going to
beam them aboard
directly onto the Bridge.
But, Captain,
will they not protest?
Let them.
My apologies
if I interrupted a waltz.
Why have you
brought us here
against our will?
I want to end the suffering
of one of my crew members.
I don't understand.
Kevin does.
He's the cause.
At first,
I couldn't understand
why your house survived
the holocaust
when the others hadn't.
Then it occurred to me--
it had been destroyed.
That dwelling
where you served me tea
where you danced
your waltzes
is a reproduction.
Real to the touch,
but capable of being created
destroyed and created,
all in a whim.
You're joking
with us, Captain.
Can't you see, this
is hurting my husband.
Rishon, hear
what he has to say.
PICARD:
More than anything else
you wanted the Enterprise
away from Rana
because the house,
the plot of land
your very existence
were incongruities
that you were not prepared
to explain.
The warship, another recreation
tried to chase us away
twice and failed.
But when I came to your house
the second time
I provided you
with the only condition
that would make
the Enterprise leave--
your deaths.
You did your best
to satisfy that condition.
I'm deeply sorry
about the woman.
I will help her
but I must know what you intend
to do with me afterwards.
You'll be taken
to the nearest Starbase
and held responsible
for the attack on the Enterprise
and, possibly, the deaths
of 11,000 people.
No, he never
killed anyone.
The destruction of the planet
happened just as I told you.
PICARD:
But you haven't told us
the whole story--
how it ended,
the part about... Rishon.
What is he saying?
Rishon, I can touch you.
I can hear your voice.
I can smell your perfume.
In every respect,
you are a real person
with your own mind
and beliefs
but you do not exist.
You died, along with the others,
defending the colony.
He recreated you,
just as he recreated the house.
You're the only
living thing
that really exists on Rana
and though you look human,
you're not.
LA FORGE:
He's in turbolift.
Let him go.
WORF:
Captain, he is dangerous.
So dangerous, Mr. Worf,
that he could have
destroyed us
in an instant
had he wished.
Track him.
Alert the crew to
keep clear of him.
I want him to understand
we mean him no harm.
Will he return
to the planet?
If he is the creature
of conscience I
believe him to be
he has someone
to help first.
I've taken the music
from her mind.
She's all right now.
She's sleeping.
She was beginning
to sense who I really was.
I've lived as a human
for over 50 years
but I couldn't hide from her.
She has suffered because
of my pride and selfishness.
It will not happen again.
PICARD:
What happened on Rana IV?
The truth, this
time all of it.
Very well.
For what it's worth.
I am a Douwd
an immortal being of disguises
and false surroundings.
I have lived in this galaxy
for many thousands of years
although, until today, no one
has known my true identity.
Once, while traveling
in human form
I chanced to fall in love
with an Earth woman.
I put aside my powers
and became her husband.
Our life was
happy and rich.
Eventually, we came
to this planet
to live our final years.
Now she is dead.
She never knew
what I really was.
Your colony was attacked
by a warship...
Belonging
to the Husnock
a species
of hideous intelligence
that knew only aggression
and destruction.
I could have destroyed them
with a mere thought
but I did not do so.
You had the power to stop them,
but you didn't?
I refused to for the same reason
that I refused to stop
the Enterprise.
I will not kill.
So you let the colonists
fight a hopeless battle.
I tried to fool the Husnock
as I tried to fool you
but it only made them angrier
and more cruel.
And then, what you
most feared happened.
Rishon went to fight
with the colonists
and died with them.
How I wish I could have died
with her.
But you couldn't.
You were left alone.
Yes.
I saw her broken body.
I went insane.
My hatred exploded
and in an instant of grief...
I destroyed the Husnock.
Why did you try to hide this
from all of us?
Was it out of guilt
for not helping Rishon
and the others
when they were alive?
No, no, no, no, no.
You don't understand
the scope of my crime.
I didn't kill just one Husnock,
or a hundred or a thousand...
I killed them all.
All Husnock...
everywhere.
Are 11,000 people
worth 50 billion?
Is the love of a woman
worth the destruction
of an entire species?
This is the sin I tried so hard
to keep you from learning--
why I wanted
to chase you from Rana.
We're not qualified
to be your judges.
We have no law
to fit your crime.
You're free to return
to the planet
and to make Rishon live again.
Helm, break orbit.
Full impulse.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43153.7.
We are departing the Rana
system for Starbase 133.
We leave behind a being
of extraordinary power
and conscience.
I'm not certain if he should
be praised or condemned
only that he should
be left alone.