Captain's log,
stardate 43173.5
We are en route to Mintaka 3
where a three-man Federation
anthropological field team
has been studying
the inhabitants.
Our mission is to resupply
the outpost
and repair their
malfunctioning reactor.
Mr. La Forge, report.
Well, we finished replicating
the parts they'll need.
But what I don't
understand is why
a three-man station
would need a reactor
capable of producing
4.2 gigawatts.
RIKER: Enough to power
a small phaser bank
or a subspace relay
station or...
Or a hologram
generator.
Oh, a "duck blind."
Right, they're
anthropologists.
Mm-hmm, who are studying an
extended family of Mintakans
at close range, from a
camouflaged observation post.
According to Dr. Barron's
preliminary reports,
the Mintakans are
proto-Vulcan humanoids
at the Bronze Age level.
Quite peaceful,
and highly rational.
Which is not surprising,
considering how closely
their evolution
parallels Vulcan.
Captain, incoming transmission
from Mintaka 3.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
On screen.
Barron to Enterprise.
Our temporary repairs
have failed.
The reactor is now inoperative.
PICARD:
Do you have battery backup?
Three hours at best.
Captain, if we
increase to warp 7,
we can be there in 23 minutes.
PICARD:
Make it so.
We're on our way.
( explosion,
woman groaning )
We've lost contact, sir.
Increase to warp 9.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
GEORDI: The framework's
still charged, so watch it.
Why did we have
to come so early?
When the sun reaches
its zenith,
I have to be ready to
take the measurements.
You'll be ready. You've read
the sundial hundreds of times.
Yes, Father, but never as
the appointed record keeper.
You're taking your duties
quite seriously.
Your mother would have
been very proud of you.
What is that?
Up there, Father.
What is it?
I don't know.
Keep work--
Palmer?
BEVERLY: It's all right,
it's all right.
The holographic generator
is now functioning, sir.
All we need now
is power.
Almost there.
You wait here, Oji.
BEVERLY: Enterprise, beam
Martinez and his patient
directly to sick bay.
( gasps )
DATA:
Commander...
( screaming )
RIKER:
Doctor, be careful.
BEVERLY:
I've got to get down there.
Crusher to Enterprise.
Medical emergency.
Two to beam directly
to sick bay.
SICK BAY:
Aye, Doctor.
That should do it.
You increased the levels
of tricortisine?
PICARD:
Dr. Crusher.
Before you start quoting
me the prime directive,
he'd already seen us.
The damage was done.
It was either bring him
aboard or let him die.
Then why didn't you
let him die?
Because we were responsible
for his injuries.
I'm not sure that I concur
with that reasoning, Doctor.
But now that he's here,
you must remove all memory
of his encounter with
the away team.
By erasing
short-term recall?
It has been
accomplished before.
I am familiar with
Dr. Pulaski's technique.
But I can't guarantee
it'll be effective
on Mintakan
brain chemistry.
Their lysosome levels
are much lower.
BARRON: Wait, no, no!
We must evacuate.
Dr. Barron, you're
on the Enterprise.
You're safe.
The others?
Dr. Warren is here.
We are doing all we can.
BARRON:
And Palmer, where is Palmer?
PICARD:
He's still on Mintaka 3.
BARRON:
Picard, you have to find him.
PICARD: We will.
BARRON: He may be hurt.
Rest assured, we shall not
leave until he is located.
Thank you, Picard.
Picard to bridge.
Report.
WORF: Scans of the planet
detect no humans, Captain.
Very well, put us in
a close orbit.
WORF: Sir, the close orbit
will increase sensor efficiency
by only four percent.
I want that four percent,
Lieutenant.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Picard out.
Picard.
Damn.
Well, Doctor,
your next task is clear.
Oji?
Oji!
Father?
Here.
Oji.
Father!
I thought I'd...
Oji!
...never see you again.
When you and the
woman vanished,
I was sure
you were dead.
I think I was.
But I was brought
back to life.
Oji, I awoke in
an incredible place
and my wounds
were gone.
I had been healed.
How is that possible?
Long ago, our people believed
in beings with great powers.
And those beings
made the rains come.
They told the sun
when to rise.
They caused all life to
be born, to grow, to die.
But those are just tales,
Father, old superstitions.
But perhaps the beliefs
of our ancestors are true.
Nothing else can explain
what's happened.
Everything has
changed now, Oji.
We must tell the others.
Barron is stable,
but Warren is still critical.
Palmer is missing.
Scan of the planet shows
Mintakan life-forms only.
No humans, however...
The area around
the duck blind
exhibits karst topography--
sinkholes, underground
rivers and caverns.
And the rock strata
contains a high concentration
of thallium compound,
which may be obstructing
our sensor beams.
So, if Palmer, in his
delirium, fled into a cave,
we may be unable to
detect his life signs.
Correct, sir.
Captain, if he is still alive,
he needs medical attention.
We must send an away
team to locate him.
TROI:
But our presence must not
interfere with the cultural
development of the Mintakans.
Agreed. Further contamination
must be prevented.
I have a suggestion.
RIKER: First Officer's log,
stardate 43174.2.
Counselor Troi and I
are beaming down
to Mintaka 3
to locate Dr. Palmer,
and to determine the extent
of the cultural contamination.
Dr. Crusher has
temporarily altered
our features and skin color.
She's also implanted
subcutaneous communicators,
so that any transmissions
we receive
will be inaudible
to the Mintakans.
Riker to Enterprise.
Do you hear me?
DATA: Perfectly, Commander.
I will be monitoring
you continuously.
Mintakan emotions
are quite interesting.
Like the Vulcans, they have
highly ordered minds.
A very sensible people.
For example, Mintakan women
precede their mates.
It's a signal to other women.
"This man's taken.
Get your own"?
Not precisely.
More like, "If you
want his services,
I'm the one you have
to negotiate with."
What kind of "services"?
All kinds.
They are a sensible race.
FATHER:
I understand your skepticism.
If it hadn't happened to me,
I would find it difficult
to accept as well.
OJI: But it did happen,
just as we've said.
FATHER: Fento, you know the
legends better than anyone.
Do they not speak of beings
like the kind I've seen...
Who could vanish
like smoke?
There are the stories
of the overseer,
who could appear
and disappear at will.
And couldn't this overseer
heal the dead?
FENTO: He had supreme power,
or so our ancestors believed.
I believe I have seen
the overseer.
He is called... the Picard.
Uh-oh.
His memory is intact.
The procedure
didn't work.
Liko, all this talk
of supernatural beings,
no one has believed that for
countless generations.
Just as we
no longer believe
that the stars
control our fates
or the spirits of the
dead haunt the living.
Nuria, I'm not saying that
all the old beliefs are true.
But I did see the Picard.
And I was restored
back to life.
We are visitors.
We've come to trade
our cloth.
May we speak?
Please do.
We welcome outsiders.
I am Nuria.
I am Troi,
and this is Riker.
You had a very
interesting dream.
Dream?
It was real.
My father and I both
witnessed these beings.
If you are father
and daughter,
you may well have
shared the same dream.
That is not reasonable.
Is that any less
reasonable than being
magically transformed
to another place
by the Picard?
MAN:
Nuria!
LIKO:
It has to be Palmer.
The one the Picard
wished to find.
Remarkable-- you were
speaking the truth.
The Picard will be pleased.
( overlapping chatter )
Riker to Picard.
PICARD:
Go ahead, Number One.
We have a problem.
The contamination?
RIKER: It's worse than
we suspected.
The Mintakans are beginning
to believe in a god.
RIKER: And the one
they've chosen is you.
Picard, you must beam
Palmer aboard immediately.
Without medical attention--
It's not simple as that.
He is surrounded
by Mintakans.
If he should dematerialize
before their eyes--
It will slightly increase
the cultural contamination
which already exists.
A small price for
saving Palmer's life.
Number One, is there any
chance of freeing Palmer
and transporting up unseen?
We can try.
PICARD:
Try hard.
Picard out.
Picard, I must protest.
You're endangering
Palmer with this delay.
I am aware of that.
But each of us,
including Dr. Palmer,
took an oath that we would
uphold the prime directive--
if necessary, with our lives.
HALI: Rego and I were
hunting off the third ridge.
We followed a hornbuck
into a cave.
The stranger
was there asleep.
This Palmer is one of
the overseer's servants?
Yes, the Picard
has many servants.
Isn't that true, Fento?
According to legend.
But if this Palmer is a
servant of the overseer,
what was he doing
in the cave?
Perhaps he ran away.
Or he failed the Picard somehow
and was hiding from him.
Then we should bind him,
in case he wakes
and tries to escape.
It's senseless
for this stranger
to be held captive.
All this talk
of the overseer--
it's old superstitions.
NURIA:
I disagree.
All the evidence indicates
that the overseer exists.
And I heard
the Picard say
he wanted to
find Palmer.
( group muttering )
Then by keeping Palmer safe,
we will please the Picard.
And he will grant us
favors in return.
Favors?
It is said that the
overseer is all-powerful.
He can provide
gentle winters,
plentiful hunting,
fertile crops, anything.
He could even bring back
those who have died.
NURIA:
It's agreed.
We will save Palmer
for the Picard.
( group agreeing )
I've seen another one
like Palmer.
LIKO: Another servant
of the Picard?
He's headed towards the caves.
Fento, stay and
bind Palmer.
( group chattering )
Over there.
Well, that knot won't hold.
If I may?
Please do.
You need a knot that'll
tighten under pressure.
Let me show you.
Father, the sun's
reaching its zenith.
If I don't go
to measure--
Go.
Forgive me, friend,
but the stranger
must be set free.
Riker?
Riker to Enterprise.
Lock on and prepare to beam us
directly to sick bay,
but hang on for my signal.
DATA:
Acknowledged, Commander.
Riker, stop!
Riker!
Oji?!
It's Riker.
He's taking Palmer!
Hali! Yari!
Don't let her escape!
I'm clear.
Energize.
Data, has Counselor Troi
beamed up?
DATA:
Negative, Commander.
Sensors show she is in the midst
of a group of Mintakans.
Damn.
NURIA:
He is all right.
Hali, find Riker
and Palmer.
Why did you and Riker
take Palmer from us?
We did not take Palmer.
TROI: We set him free.
Riker and I do not believe in
these fables about an overseer.
LIKO: Don't you realize
what you've done?
You have angered the Picard,
and we may all suffer for it.
I know. I've seen him.
He is all-powerful.
Fento, weren't there
stories about the overseer
destroying those
who offended him?
Stories, nothing more.
Liko, we'll get
Palmer back.
Riker was carrying him.
They can't have gone far.
Still, the Picard may blame us
for letting Palmer escape.
Perhaps we should punish her.
Let the overseer know that
she and Riker acted alone.
We will keep Troi captive.
That's not enough.
You would have us harm her?
If it will hold off
the Picard's anger, yes.
I've seen how powerful he is.
I am unwilling
to hurt her needlessly.
We will wait for Hali to return.
And if they
don't find Palmer?
Then we may do
as Liko suggests.
Doctor, you believe
the Mintakans
are capable of
harming Counselor Troi?
They are not normally
a violent people,
but these are
extraordinary circumstances.
They're trying
to comprehend
what they believe
to be a god.
( sighs )
Recommendations?
The Mintakans wish to
please the overseer,
but they can only
guess what he wants.
They need a sign.
Are you suggesting...?
You must go down to Mintaka 3.
Masquerading as a god?!
Absolutely out of the question.
The prime directive--
BARRON:
Has already been violated.
The damage is done.
All we can do now
is minimize it.
By sanctioning
their false beliefs?
By giving them guidelines.
Letting them know what
the overseer expects of them.
Dr. Barron, I cannot.
I will not impose a set of
commandments on these people.
To do so violates the very
essence of the prime directive.
Like it or not,
we have rekindled
the Mintakans belief
in the overseer.
RIKER: And are you saying
that this belief
will eventually become a
religion?
It's inevitable.
And without guidance,
that religion
could degenerate
into inquisitions,
holy wars, chaos.
Horrifying.
Dr. Barron...
your report describes
how rational these people are.
Millennia ago,
they abandoned their belief
in the supernatural.
Now, you are asking me to
sabotage that achievement.
To send them back into the
dark ages of superstition
and ignorance and fear.
No!
We will find some way to
undo the damage we've caused.
Number One, tell me
about this group's leader.
Nuria-- exceptionally
clear-minded, sensible.
The Mintakans
trust her judgment.
If we could convince her
that you are not a god...
She might be able to
persuade the others.
And how do you
propose to convince her?
She believes that Picard
is a magical figure.
I'm gonna show her
how the magic works.
I'm gonna bring her aboard.
DATA: Counselor, sensors
indicate five Mintakans
in your immediate
vicinity.
Four are motionless.
The fifth is eight meters away,
proceeding south.
Is Nuria one of these five?
Mm-hmm.
Was that intended
as an affirmative?
Yes, Data, it was.
Is Nuria the closest
of the five?
TROI: Mm-mm.
Negative.
DATA: Is Nuria
the one in motion?
( clears throat )
Mm-hmm.
Lock sensors on Nuria.
Locked on.
We can beam Nuria
aboard at will.
Data, when sensors
indicate that she's alone,
beam her directly to
Transporter Room One.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Hoy.
DATA:
Captain, Nuria is alone.
I'll handle this.
Nuria.
Don't be afraid.
No one is going to harm you.
Who...?
I am Jean-Luc...
Picard.
( gasps )
Please, get up.
Get up. You must
not kneel to me.
You do not wish it?
I do not deserve it.
Look at me.
Feel the warmth
of my hand.
The rhythm of my pulse.
I'm not a supreme being.
I'm flesh and blood,
like you.
Not like me--
Like you.
Different in appearance, yes.
But we are both
living beings.
We are born, we grow,
we live...
and we die.
In all the ways that
matter, we are alike.
But you are the Picard.
There is something
I want you to see.
( gasps )
Oh, what a wondrous place.
Even the walls
obey your command.
Wondrous, yes,
but not miraculous.
The... doors...
merely work differently
from the ones you know.
( gasps )
That is my home?
Seen from far, far above.
Yet we do not fall.
I never imagined I would see
the clouds from the other side.
Your powers are
truly boundless.
Nuria...
Your people
live in huts.
Was it always so?
No.
We have found remnants
of tools in caves.
Our ancestors must
have lived there.
So, why do you
now live in huts?
Huts are better.
Caves are dark and wet.
So, if huts are better,
why did you once live in caves?
The most reasonable
explanation would be
that at one time, we did not
know how to make huts.
Just as at one time,
you did not know
how to weave cloth,
how to make a bow.
That would be
reasonable.
Someone invented a hut.
Someone invented a bow,
who taught others,
who taught their children,
who built a stronger hut,
who built a better bow,
who taught
their children.
Now, Nuria, suppose one of
your cave-dwelling ancestors
were to see you as
you are today.
What would she think?
I don't know.
Well, put yourself
in her place.
You see, she cannot kill a
hornbuck at a great distance.
You can.
You have a power she lacks.
Only because I have a bow.
She has never
seen a bow.
It doesn't exist
in her world.
To you,
it's a simple tool.
To her... it's magic.
I suppose she might think so.
Now, how would she
react to you?
I think she would fear me.
Just as you fear me.
I do not fear you any longer.
Good.
That's good.
You see...
my people once
lived in caves.
And we then learned
to build huts,
and in time, to build
ships like this one.
Perhaps one day, my people
will travel above the skies.
Of that, I have absolutely
no doubt.
( thunderclap )
It's not the season
for lightning.
It must be a warning.
We've had storms
like this before.
( thunderclap )
Not like this one.
It must mean
something.
The Picard is
angry with us.
He blames us for
letting Palmer escape.
Liko, we don't know
that the overseer
is responsible
for this storm.
LIKO:
Will he also send floods?
My wife died in
last year's floods.
Will we all die now?
( thunderclap )
We must find Nuria.
Picard, you've
shown me wonders
I could never
have imagined.
And I am grateful to you
beyond words.
Might I request
something for my people?
You are indeed a leader.
You've shown me
such generosity.
I wish my people
could share in it.
Six Mintakans died in
a flood last winter.
Four of them, children.
Would you bring them
back to life?
That is not in my power.
Why?
You restored Liko's life.
Did the six who were killed
offend you in some way?
Did I offend you?
Should I have ordered
the death of Troi?
Please, you must tell me
if there's anything I can
do to change your mind.
I've failed to get through
to you, haven't I?
Despite all my efforts.
( thunderclap )
Nuria can't be found.
No one knows
where she's gone.
Hali, any sign of
Palmer or Riker?
They have escaped us.
We searched everywhere.
( thunderclap )
What do we do now, Father?
We must do as
the Picard wishes.
Punish those
responsible.
Nuria would not
allow us to do that--
Nuria isn't here.
We can't wait.
( gasping )
Crusher to Picard.
I think we're going
to lose Warren.
PICARD:
On my way.
I'm here, Mary.
( gasping )
BEVERLY:
Prepare two C.C.s of norep.
I'm sorry.
Picard, you could
not save her?
No.
You do have limits.
You are not masters
of life and death.
No, we're not.
We can cure
many diseases.
We can repair injuries.
We can even extend life.
But for all our knowledge,
all our advances,
we are just as
mortal as you are.
We are just as powerless
to prevent the inevitable.
You are a remarkable people,
but you are not
superior beings.
My people must be made
to understand that.
Liko, you don't want
to kill me.
I have no choice.
I must do as
the Picard wishes.
Are you sure you know
what he wants?
That's the problem
with believing in a
supernatural being--
trying to determine
what he wants.
We must do something.
But what if it's the
wrong thing, Father?
Picard, we need your guidance.
Is it your wish
that this woman
should die?
Answer us.
Speak.
Liko.
The Picard!
The overseer
has come.
No, Liko.
Liko, I am a man.
I am not the overseer.
I am a traveller
from a faraway land.
Nothing more.
But you have
restored my life.
I am your servant.
You are nobody's
servant, Liko.
I neither desire your
obedience nor your worship.
Picard speaks the truth.
I have visited his people.
I have seen
how they live
and how they die.
When death takes one
of their loved ones,
they are as helpless
as we are.
Then... how was I
brought back to life?
Liko, you were not dead.
Picard's people have
a knowledge that we lack.
They are able to heal
wounds that we cannot.
No, no, he can bring
back the dead.
Show them, Picard.
You can bring back
my wife to me.
I cannot.
Why?
Why won't you do this for me?
Have I failed you
in some way?
Are you angry with me?
I'm not angry with you.
Well, then I beg you,
bring her back to me.
I will give you my life
in exchange.
Please!
Take back what
you gave me.
Give it to her.
Let her live.
It is beyond my power.
Nothing is beyond
your power.
You are the overseer.
I will prove it.
Liko!
If you believe
I am all-powerful,
then you cannot hurt me.
If, however, I am
telling the truth...
and I am mortal...
you will kill me.
But if the only proof you
will believe is my death...
then shoot.
Liko, don't do it!
Father, no!
( whimpering )
Captain's log, supplemental.
Dr. Crusher has repaired
my injury
with her usual skill.
Mr. La Forge will supervise
the dismantling
of the observation post
after I make one last visit
to Mintaka 3.
Now, Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE: Aye, sir.
What is that?
It is a place where we
can watch your people.
But why?
To study you,
to understand your ways.
Discontinue, Mr. La Forge.
Picard, why would a
people so advanced
want to learn about us?
We were once
as you are now.
To study you is to
understand ourselves.
But why do you have to
hide yourself from us?
Because their presence
would affect us
just as it
affected me.
It is our highest law,
that we shall not interfere
with other cultures.
Then revealing yourselves
was an accident.
Oh, yes.
And now,
we must leave you.
Why? There's so much
you can teach us.
But that, too,
would be interference.
You must progress
in your own way.
So, we will.
You have taught us there is
nothing beyond our reach.
Not even the stars.
Paki?
I wish you good
journeys, Picard.
Remember my people.
Always.