DATA:
Commander,
away team reporting in.
Lieutenant Worf standing by.
This is Riker.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
WORF:
The archaeologists
have identified
the markings in these caverns.
This planet was apparently
once home to a race
known as the Koinonians.
What do we know about them,
Data?
The Koinonians were
an intelligent culture
which became embroiled in a war
that lasted
for several
generations.
Our best evidence
indicates they
destroyed themselves.
WORF:
We have completed our survey
of the third tunnel
and will proceed
into the ceremonial chamber.
Affirmative.
Enterprise out.
Destroyed
themselves, Data?
According
to historical records
this will be
the first opportunity
for a Federation team...
Captain, beam them up quickly!
WORF:
Captain, emergency beam-up!
Enterprise, emergency.
Severe injuries!
Transporter Room?
O'BRIEN:
I've got them, Captain.
Beam them straight to Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher, incoming wounded.
Away team is on board, Captain.
CRUSHER:
One dead on arrival.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43198.7.
The Enterprise
remains in standard orbit
while we investigate
the tragedy
which has struck the away team.
Lieutenant Marla Aster,
ship's archaeologist
has been killed in what should
have been a routine mission.
Whatever the explanation
it will not bring back
a valued and trusted officer.
Lieutenant?
We had completed
our investigation
of the third tunnel.
Our scans indicated no weapons
or traps of any kind.
Lieutenant Aster was
three meters behind me.
An explosive device went off.
There was no warning.
Lieutenant Aster
bore the full brunt
of the detonation.
Lieutenant Aster is survived
by a son, Jeremy, 12 years old.
He's aboard the
Enterprise, sir.
And his father?
He's also deceased.
His only living relatives
are an aunt and uncle
residing on Earth.
Where is he now?
In class.
I've alerted the teacher
to expect us.
WORF:
Captain!
I must accompany you.
I commanded the away team.
I appreciate your
offer, Lieutenant.
This is my
responsibility.
Picard to Bridge.
RIKER:
Yes, Captain.
Assign Commander La Forge
to lead
another away team
to the dig site.
I want to know
why this happened.
Yes, Captain.
I will be with Counselor Troi
and young Jeremy Aster.
I understand.
Riker out.
He had to do
the same thing for me.
Do you know Jeremy well?
But I know what this
is going to be like for him.
It's part of life
in Starfleet, Wesley.
I know.
They're very careful
to prepare us for anything.
But still...
I know.
How do you get used to it?
To telling them?
You hope you never do.
I sense the weight
of this duty on you, Captain.
I really wonder...
Halt.
I've always believed that
carrying children on a starship
is a very questionable policy.
Serving on a starship means
accepting certain risks,
certain dangers.
Did Jeremy Aster
make that choice?
Death and loss are
an integral part
of life everywhere.
Leaving him on Earth would
not have protected him.
No, but the Earth
isn't likely
to be ordered
to the Neutral Zone
or to repel a Romulan attack.
It was my command
which sent
his mother to her death.
She understood her mission
and my duty.
Will he?
In time, and with help.
Wesley Crusher does.
He does, and so will Jeremy.
Resume.
Jeremy, I have some bad news.
There's been an accident.
Your mother... has died.
How, sir?
An explosive device
at the mission site.
She died instantly.
I understand.
Jeremy, I know your mother
loved you very much.
I'm told that
your father is also dead.
Yes, sir.
He died five years ago
from a Rushton infection.
I'm all alone now, sir.
Jeremy,
on the Starship Enterprise
no one is alone.
No one.
Excuse me, sir.
Am I intruding?
No. Sit down.
How well did you know
Lieutenant Aster?
We spent some time together.
Not very well.
How well did you know her?
Why do you ask?
Well, you just asked me.
But... why do you
ask the question?
Since her death, I have been
asked several times
to define how well
I knew Lieutenant Aster.
And I heard you ask Wesley
on the Bridge
how well he knew Jeremy.
Does the question of familiarity
have some bearing on death?
Do you remember how we all felt
when Tasha died?
I do not sense
the same feelings of absence
that I associate
with Lieutenant Yar
although I cannot say
precisely why.
Just human nature, Data.
Human nature, sir?
We feel a loss more intensely
when it's a friend.
Hmm.
But should not the feelings
run just as deep
regardless of who has died?
Maybe they should, Data.
Maybe if we felt any loss
as keenly as we felt the death
of one close to us
human history
would be a lot less bloody.
La Forge to Riker.
You're back, Geordi?
Yes, sir, and we brought back
a souvenir.
LA FORGE:
There are five more just like it
all identical to the one
that killed Lieutenant Aster.
They employ a subspace
proximity detonator.
A normal tricorder
would never detect it.
How long would you say
they've been there, Data?
It comes from the time
of the Koinonian wars, sir.
RIKER:
Did you find them all, Geordi?
Yeah, but, uh...
Well, it seemed like they were
left there to be found.
Left by whom?
There are no indications
of life on this planet.
I don't know, Captain
but it was pretty obvious
that they'd been recently
pulled out of the ground
and defused.
I have made my report
to the Captain.
I'm more interested
in how you feel
about what happened.
I sense great anger.
I cannot seek revenge
against an enemy who was turned
to dust centuries ago.
Her death was senseless.
The last victim
of a forgotten war.
Go on.
There is nothing more
to be said.
A person died
under your command.
It may happen again.
If you can't learn
to release the anger
and the guilt
to talk about it...
A leader must stand alone,
as Captain Picard does.
Captain Picard talks to me.
Then, may I seek your counsel
on my plan
to make R'uustai with the boy.
The bonding?
It is my right.
It's very generous, Worf,
but he's not a Klingon child.
He has different
sensibilities.
He is an orphan.
I am an orphan.
He will understand.
Right now, there isn't
much he can understand.
He's holding all
his feelings inside.
Children often feel
that they must be true to
the memory of a lost parent.
If you offer them
affection too soon
they can feel guilty
returning that affection--
as if they're betraying
the love of the parent.
I only wish to honor his mother.
I know.
And I understand this
means a great deal to you.
But you must be prepared.
He's very angry, too.
But his anger is
deep inside him.
When he touches it,
it will strike out
in many directions,
including yours.
Be with him.
Talk to him, but
don't rush this.
When he's ready,
we'll know.
JEREMY:
Captain Patches, we have
an alien ship in front of us.
What shall we do, Captain?
Oh, no, we've been hit,
Captain.
We're going down!
MAN ( chuckling ):
That was great.
Now, uh, let's
get a shot of Mom.
What are you doing?
I'll turn your lens
into pottery shards.
Go away. Go away.
Go away!
Over there, over there.
( cat meows )
Patches.
Captain Patches...
( door chimes )
...is coming in for a landing
on the sofa.
Oh, no! He's going to crash...
( turns off device )
Jeremy Aster?
I am Lieutenant Worf.
May I enter?
You were in command
of the away team.
Yes.
I was with Lieutenant Aster,
your mother
when she died.
You're a Klingon, aren't you?
Yes.
We studied about Klingons
in school.
What did they teach you
about us?
You used to be
our enemies.
Did they also teach you
that every Klingon hopes
to die in the line of duty
as your mother did?
In my tradition, we do not
grieve the loss of the body.
We celebrate the releasing
of the spirit.
I understand death.
They teach us all about it.
Jeremy Aster, we may
both understand it
but we must bring meaning
to your mother's death.
Perhaps we can do it together.
( door chimes )
Come.
Counselor.
How is the boy?
He's being very brave.
Good.
No, he has to get past brave.
He's very angry
and he has to learn
how to express that anger
before he can really say
good-bye to his mother.
How can we help?
Well, I've asked Beverly
if we might get Wesley
to talk to Jeremy about
his father's death.
Oh.
The one unusual
element is Worf.
Oh?
In many ways, he's suffering
as badly as the boy.
He wishes to involve Jeremy
in a Klingon ceremony
called R'uustai--
the bonding.
I know of that.
Well, perhaps it will be
helpful to both of them.
I don't think Jeremy's ready
to accept Worf right now.
Perhaps later, but...
it will have to be
handled most delicately.
As you always do.
I break the unpleasant news
and there
my responsibility ends
but you...
you have to stay with them
through the entire
grieving process.
We deal with our pain
in many different ways
but, over the years, I've
discovered it's in joy
that the uniqueness of each
individual is revealed.
If I can help a person
back to a state of joy...
Well, my role
has its rewards.
RIKER:
Captain, we're picking up
an energy field
on the planet's surface.
Location?
Two kilometers north of
the away team's beam-down point.
Indeed?
Full scan.
DATA:
Inconclusive, Captain.
Sir, I'm sensing a
presence on the planet.
Very vague.
Life-form?
I can't be sure.
The emotions of the
crew are particularly
strong right now.
It's difficult
to filter them out.
Data, scan analysis
on main viewer.
Hi.
Troi stopped by
a little while ago.
She was wondering
if you might be willing
to talk to Jeremy Aster
at some point.
Me?
What for?
About your dad.
What am I going to tell him?
It would help him
to talk to somebody
who's been through this.
We had each other, Wes.
He doesn't have anyone
to lean on right now
and he might be more comfortable
talking to someone who's not
that much older than he is.
Okay, I'll think about it.
Okay.
Do you ever think
about him, Mom?
Your father?
Sure, I do.
Sometimes, I can't even remember
what his face looks like.
It scares me.
It happens to all of us, Wes.
Sometimes...
I can't get his face
out of my mind.
Today... today, it's like...
I can see it all as clearly
as if it were yesterday.
I can remember
the way Dad looked
when he hugged me good-bye.
Captain Picard's eyes
when he came to tell us...
Data, run comparison
of known phenomena.
The pattern has no exact match
in Federation records, sir.
Is it alive?
A possibility.
LA FORGE:
Captain, I'm getting
an unusual magnetic flux reading
from the anti-matter
containment pods.
My god.
JEREMY:
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Okay, you got
ten seconds more, Mom.
No peeking.
Come on, Patches, in here.
Shh.
Okay, Mom, we're ready.
ASTER:
Jeremy, I'm getting closer.
Jeremy?
I'm going to find you.
You must be in here somewhere.
Jeremy?
Mom?!
All systems
are functioning normally.
Still, there's this fluctuation
in the containment field.
I can't account for it.
Data, is this possibly related
to the energy fields
on the planet?
There is a beam of highly
charged particles
emanating from the planet, sir
but I cannot pinpoint
the location yet.
Captain, there's a presence
on the Enterprise.
An alien presence?
DATA:
No intruder noted
by the sensors, sir.
There is a presence.
Security, all decks,
yellow alert.
Possible intruder.
They said you were dead.
There was a mistake.
It's okay.
But there was an explosion.
You were hurt.
I'm fine.
You mustn't think
anymore about this.
The important thing is
I'm never going
to leave you again.
I think somebody needs a hug.
We have to go now.
Where?
To the planet.
That's where we're
going to live now.
We're not going to stay
on the Enterprise anymore?
No, we're going to live
in a home.
Just like we used to
on Earth.
You'll see.
I promise.
( door chimes )
Lieutenant Worf,
did they tell you?
It was a mistake.
She didn't die.
She's alive.
Jeremy, come here.
Lieutenant Worf,
it's all right.
I'm here for the boy.
Lieutenant Worf
to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
Lieutenant Aster
is in her quarters.
Repeat, Worf?
Lieutenant Aster is here.
In her quarters, with the boy.
PICARD:
Do not provoke her
or interfere in any way
until I arrive.
Picard out.
Number One, have security
moving that way
but tell them
to keep their distance.
You have the Bridge.
Counselor.
There is nothing
to worry about.
I'm going to take care of
Jeremy and make him happy.
It's time to go.
Where are you taking the child?
To the planet.
Come, Jeremy.
Worf to Picard.
They're leaving their quarters.
Captain, I believe we're headed
for Transporter Room 3.
We're on our way.
Chief O'Brien.
Jeremy and I are going
down to the surface.
Who are you?
I'm Marla Aster.
It's my mother, Captain.
She's alive.
What do you want?
To take my child
down to the planet.
I cannot permit that.
The boy is my responsibility.
I'm here to care for him.
He needs me.
Why do you resist?
Because I don't know
who or what you are.
Can't you see who it is,
Captain?
Jeremy, she appears to be
your mother, but she is not.
What do you mean?
You're confusing the boy.
Hey!
Wait, stop, no!
No, wait, stop!
Mom!
Mom?
Jeremy.
Wait a minute!
Come on.
Would you just let...
Jeremy...
Let go of me!
She was right there!
What did you do to her?
Jeremy, I don't know
what that was
but it was not
your mother.
You saw her.
She was here.
Your mother's dead.
But I touched her.
She was real.
Why would your real mother
want you to go
down to the planet?
There's nothing there
but dust and rocks.
( cat meows )
It's my house.
It's my house on Earth.
Exactly the
way it was.
Remember, Jeremy?
How did you do it?
Does it matter?
Yes, it matters.
I am trying to understand
your resistance.
You spoke of
rocks and dust
on the planet.
I decided to show you
what awaits us there.
Why would you create
this fantasy?
It's his home.
And it makes you
happy, doesn't it?
But it's not real.
Isn't it?
Jeremy...
isn't that really Patches?
( meows )
He knows me.
It's him.
It's real.
It's all real.
TROI:
No, it's not.
Could your real mother
just make all this appear?
You must not
stay here.
Come with me.
( Patches purring )
I can't.
Is the boy in any danger?
TROI:
I don't think so.
She seems to want to help him.
Help him?
By easing his pain.
She's very confused
by our resistance, Captain.
Troi, would it be wise
to remove Jeremy
from his cabin?
He doesn't want to leave.
I would not recommend
taking him by force.
She offers him everything.
All we can offer is the cold
reality of his mother's death.
CRUSHER:
What would you choose?
If somebody came along
and offered to give you
back your mother,
father, or husband
would any of us
say "no" so easily?
Counselor, stay with them
in Jeremy's quarters.
We'll try and put an end
to this from here.
Understood.
( both laughing )
Data, can you determine
for certain
that the energy source
from the planet
is powering this creation?
The beam from the planet
is clearly tapping
into the ship's
anti-matter, Captain.
I'd say they're running
that manifestation
off our own energy.
So there are limits
to her power.
She needs the transporter
to get the boy back.
So, how do we cut
the puppet's strings?
Increasing the shield's
harmonics to match
our own anti-matter
containment fields
will probably sever the beam.
Proceed.
Deanna, stand by.
Standing by.
Jeremy, it's time
for this to end.
It's not real
and it's over now.
ASTER:
Jeremy, I'm not going
to leave you
ever again.
I won't trick you
or lie to you.
ASTER:
We'll be happy
together, Jeremy
as soon...
No.
Anti-matter containment pods
reading nominal.
The shield has severed
the beam, sir.
( console beeping )
Captain.
The energy field.
Mr. Crusher
take us out of here.
( alarm wailing )
Alien intruder,
Transporter Room 3.
Security alert.
Alien...
Security to Transporter Room 3.
Commander La Forge, Mr. Worf,
come with me.
Number One, you
have the Bridge.
( both yell )
Come, Jeremy.
We will not let them
separate us again.
We're going home.
TROI:
Captain, she's back
and she's trying to take
Jeremy off the ship again.
Acknowledged.
Engineering, this
is La Forge.
Shut down power
to all transporters.
I'm on my way.
Aye, aye, sir.
Lieutenant Worf,
to Transporter Room 3.
Bridge, seal off Deck Eight,
Corridors "A" and "B."
Engaging force fields, Captain.
Transporters down.
Energy force has left
Transporter Room 3.
Security alert, all decks.
La Forge, the intruder
may try to reinstate
transporter power.
Understood, Commander.
Bridge, release
security force field 8-B.
Hello, Jeremy.
How are you?
Are you frightened?
No.
Well, a little, sir.
Of course.
These are frightening things
that are happening
but we won't let anyone
harm you.
Counselor why
don't you take the boy
to my quarters?
No.
It's looking over everything,
Commander...
going to school.
Let's just hope
it doesn't
blow us to kingdom come
while it's figuring out
how to blow us to kingdom come.
( beeping )
Power's back
in Transporter Room 3.
Bypassing to manual override.
Shutting it down.
WORF:
Transporter is down again.
Keep it down, Geordi,
for as long as you can.
Understood, Commander.
It is only a matter
of time, Captain
before we can power
the transporters ourselves.
We?
For whom else
do you speak?
The accident
on the surface
was caused by a remnant
of an ancient and tragic era.
Two species once
shared this world--
one of energy
and one of matter.
The physical beings
you call the Koinonians
destroyed themselves
in unending, bitter wars.
The surviving life-forms
on this planet
will not tolerate
any further suffering
as a result
of that dishonorable past.
So, they have made
this possible.
They have made me possible.
I appreciate your motives...
but his mother is dead.
He must learn to live with that.
I will be every bit
his mother.
But not his mother.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Go ahead, Captain.
Will you escort Ensign Crusher
to the Aster quarters?
Yes, sir.
Picard out.
Your philosophy is curious,
Captain.
What is so noble about sorrow?
I can provide him an existence
where he will feel no pain
no anguish.
It is at the heart of our nature
to feel pain and joy.
It is an essential part
of what makes us what we are.
He is alone now in your world.
A child...
alone.
How can you know
he won't be happier with me?
For a brief moment in time,
he surely would be.
Any of us in his place
would be.
What would Jeremy do
for friends in your world?
He will have
any friends he needs.
And will you provide
for his education, his health?
His growth?
A career? A wife?
PICARD:
Yes, it's quite an undertaking
you're proposing, isn't it?
It is our duty
to make him happy again.
Do you honestly believe
he would be happy
in... this total fiction
which you wish
to create?
What reason would he have
to live?
What you're offering
him is a memory.
Something to cherish,
not to live in.
It is part of our life cycle
that we accept the death
of those we love.
Jeremy must come to terms
with his grief.
He must not cover it
or hide away from it.
You see, we are mortal.
Our time in this universe
is finite.
That is one of the truths
that all humans
must learn.
Acting Ensign Crusher
reporting as ordered, sir.
Yes, come in, Wesley.
Please stay,
Lieutenant.
Jeremy...
Wesley's father died
on a Starfleet mission
when he was younger
than you are.
TROI:
Wes...
your mother told me
you were finding it difficult
to talk to Jeremy.
Why is that?
I don't know.
I just don't want
to think about it anymore.
All this has reminded me
so much of that day.
The day I told you
your father had been killed.
As I recall, Wesley,
you took it very well.
WESLEY:
My parents had told me
about the dangers
of Starfleet missions.
I knew it could happen.
So you were prepared.
No, I wasn't prepared at all.
How can anyone
be prepared to hear
that a parent is never
coming home again?
I tried to be what everyone
expected of me--
brave and mature.
Wesley, are you saying that
you didn't want anybody to see
what you were really feeling?
Well, what were you
really feeling?
Like somebody had
kicked me in the head.
Somebody?
Go on.
You've wanted to tell him
for a long time.
I was angry... at you.
Why angry?
Why were you angry
at me, Wesley?
Were you angry at me
because I was the one
who had told you your
father was dead?
No.
Then why?
Because you led the mission.
You came home and
my father didn't.
How long were you angry
with the Captain, Wes?
For a long time
but not anymore, sir.
Not even a little.
So, Jeremy...
you must be
very angry
at Lieutenant Worf.
He was in charge of
your mother's mission
just as Captain Picard
was in command
when Wesley's father was killed.
Isn't that right?
Worf came back.
Your mother didn't.
Why?
Why weren't you
the one who died?
Why did it have
to be her?
He can't answer that.
None of us can.
Lieutenant Worf
also lost his parents.
WORF:
They were killed in battle
when I was six.
When I was alone,
humans helped me.
Let me help you.
The Marla Aster I knew
and honored
is not in this room
nor does she await you
on the planet.
She now only lives here...
and here.
Join me in the R'uustai,
the bonding.
You will become part of my
family now and for all time.
We will be brothers.
SoS jIH batlh SoH.
What does that mean?
It honors the memory
of our mothers.
We have bonded
and our families are stronger.
SoS jIH batlh SoH.