( birds singing )
Another Coco-no-no?
No, thanks.
I think I've had
enough already.
Yeah.
Yeah, me, too.
Ooh.
I almost forgot.
( plays "Hungarian Rhapsody"
by Franz Liszt )
Geordi.
Hmm?
I'm sorry.
I think I'd
better go back.
Too chilly?
I can turn down the breeze.
No, it's been a
lovely program and...
Yeah.
You're a terrific guy.
( sighs )
I just don't feel that way
about you.
( sighs )
Yeah.
Oh, knock it off.
This was the final
battle, wasn't it?
Mm-hmm. Neither side
expected Orelious IX
to be the decisive conflict.
There's not much left,
is there?
The destruction is remarkable
considering the primitive
weapons of the period.
( door opens )
Uh-oh.
I beg your pardon, Wesley.
Geordi had that big date
with Christi tonight.
He spent days putting together
the perfect program.
Looked like it ended
kind of early.
Uh-oh.
RIKER:
Commander Data
to the Bridge immediately.
Acknowledged.
We're picking up a signal.
Coordinates 211 mark 61.
It would seem to be
an ancient interplanetary code.
Mr. Data?
Confirmed, sir.
Survivors on Orelious IX
after all this time?
Not possible.
Well, hardly possible,
Number One.
Lay in a course
for the source
of the signal.
Approaching source, Captain.
Put it on the viewer.
A Promellian Battle Cruiser.
With its Lang cycle
fusion engines still intact.
( console beeping )
Sensors indicate
no life signs aboard, Captain.
I should hope not,
Mr. Data.
That ship belongs in a museum.
I'm afraid we're a little late.
That call for help
was probably initiated
over a thousand years ago.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43205.6.
We have arrived at Orelious IX
to chart the battle in which
the Menthars and Promellians
fought to their
mutual extinction.
Among the ruins,
we have found a relic--
a Promellian Battle Cruiser
that has withstood
the centuries.
Indulge me, Number One.
I would prefer it
if Lieutenant Worf and I
were able to run a security
sweep of the ship first...
No.
Captain's prerogative.
This one's mine.
We have examined
every conceivable risk.
The risks on a ship
this old and fragile
are inconceivable,
Captain.
Ghosts, perhaps?
Number One, have you...
have you never dreamed
of climbing
inside the bottle?
Sir?
The ship in the bottle.
Model airships...
I used to build them
when I was a child.
My God
I bet I had a Promellian
Battle Cruiser, too.
You ready to beam down
to the vessel?
Locked onto the Main Bridge,
Captain.
You're certain about the
atmospheric conditions, Data?
There is adequate oxygen
for life support, Commander.
It is exactly as they
left it, Number One.
In the bottle.
The ship in the bot...
Oh, good Lord, didn't anybody
here build ships in bottles
when they were boys?
I did not play with toys.
I was never a boy.
I did, sir.
Thank you, Mr. O'Brien.
Proceed.
I did. I really did.
Ships in bottles--
it was great fun.
( equipment powering down )
What's that?
Not sure.
The secondary power bus
may need adjusting.
Keep me posted.
Extraordinary.
Admirable.
They died at their posts.
Hmm...
You'd expect a bridge
layout of this era
to be clumsy, awkward
but look at this.
It's a model of simplicity--
elegant and functional.
They built this craft
for generations
and it worked.
Don't you have anything
stronger than this, Guinan?
Yes.
Would it help?
No.
( sighing heavily ):
Tell me something, Guinan.
You're a woman, right?
Yes, I can tell you I'm a woman.
What is it
that you want in a man?
You mean me, personally?
As a woman, what's
the first thing you look at?
His head.
Mmm, his mind, of course.
No, his head.
I'm attracted to bald men.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Why?
Maybe because
a bald man was kind to me once
when I was hurting.
Took care of me.
Mmm...
I'd like to do that.
Well, I take care of myself
these days.
I mean take care of somebody.
I just don't get it, Guinan.
I can field strip
a fusion reactor.
I can realign a
power transfer tunnel.
Why can't I make anything work
with a woman like Christi?
It's like I don't know
what to do
I don't know what to say.
You're doing fine with me.
You're different.
No, you're different.
But I'm not trying now.
That's my point.
What is it, Wes?
The main power return
is acting a little weird.
Define "weird."
I'm getting fluctuating
waveguide readings.
Run a maintenance sweep.
Right.
Activating power pack, Captain.
( distress signal warbling )
Mr. Worf, be sure we
get tricorder images
of their tactical display.
Aye, sir.
The source
of the distress signal
appears to be coming
from up there, Captain.
( warbling louder )
Let's put an end
to their last cry for help.
( signal stops )
Captain, I believe this is
an information storage device.
A crude analog of our own
isolinear optical chip.
Crude by our standards
today, Data
but when this ship was built
humans on Earth
were just perfecting
the mechanical clock.
They were still using
steel crossbows in battle.
Is there any way to see
what's on this?
Questionable, sir.
I believe I can supply power
to its playback unit
but its components
are quite old.
I will attempt
to amplify the image
with my tricorder.
I am Galek Sar
Captain of the Promellian
Cruiser Cleponji.
I wish anyone
who finds this record to know
my crew has behaved
courageously.
I want it recorded for all time
that I alone am responsible
for the fate that befell us
I have failed-- as a Captain
and as the man responsible
for all the souls
aboard my ship.
Picard to Enterprise.
RIKER:
Go ahead, Captain.
I think we have seen
all there is to see here.
At Mr. O'Brien's leisure,
we're ready to return.
Aye, sir.
Thrilling.
That was absolutely
thrilling.
And I was right,
Number One.
There were ghosts
on board that old ship.
One of them actually
spoke to us.
The friendly one, I hope.
My own counterpart.
The Captain's final message
praising his crew.
I hope you'll be as thoughtful
when the time comes.
Mr. Data, advise
the Astral V Annex.
This should be catalogued,
scheduled for retrieval.
Aye, sir.
( chuckles quietly )
I'm sorry, Captain.
It's just a rare pleasure
to see this side
of your personality.
Mr. Crusher, set course
for the original coordinates.
Yes, sir.
Captain, we are experiencing
a two percent drop
in energy reserves.
Compensating.
We were having
some problems while...
( alarm sounds )
Readouts indicate
we are being bombarded
with a field
of high-intensity radiation.
Shields up.
Captain, energy loss
increasing to five percent.
Yellow Alert.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Energy loss increasing, sir.
Mr. Crusher...
reverse course.
Full impulse power.
No response, sir.
Increase speed to warp one.
Engines aren't responding,
Captain.
Mr. La Forge
we need warp power now.
Matter/anti-matter
mixture ratio settings
at optimum balance.
Reaction sequence corresponding
to specified norms.
Magnetic plasma transfer
to warp field generators
per program specs.
Commander, we should be going
like a bat out of hell.
Power loss now at 12 percent,
Captain.
Red Alert.
Radiation intensity
increasing.
LA FORGE:
We'd better slow
these engines down
before we burn out
the reaction chamber.
Slow to idle, Geordi.
Is it possible?
Have we fallen into the same
snare that killed them?
A thousand-year-old booby trap?
With engines idling, the energy
loss has been limited
but our reserves
will be depleted
in less than three hours.
We won't be able to hold
our shields in place.
Mr. Worf, have you been able
to identify the source
of the radiation?
No, sir.
The radiation field
is so strong
it interferes with our sensors.
And no apparent explanation
for the energy loss?
No, sir.
Is there anything
in the history books, Data
that could give us a clue?
There are many
fascinating records
of Menthar battle strategy.
They were exceptionally
innovative.
In fact, they were
the first to use
the Kavis Teke elusive maneuver
as well
as the Passive Lure stratagem
which is comparable
to Napoleon's...
Any mention
of a situation like this?
No, sir.
I recommend that I return to
the Cruiser with an away team.
They didn't have
much success
with this problem, Commander.
No, but they knew
who their enemy was
better than we do.
They may have known
what caused the trouble.
They just didn't know
how to get out of it.
Agreed.
Mr. Worf, what would be
the impact
of lowering the shields
long enough to get
the away team out?
Negligible.
Won't do much for our energy
conservation, Captain.
That's your job,
Commander La Forge.
Determine some way to keep
the Enterprise up and running.
Data, you join Commander Riker
on the away team.
Find out what happened
on that ship.
So, why can't we move?
Computer, as we increased
our power levels
was there any counterreaction?
Affirmative.
The opposing force grew
in direct proportion
to the power output
of the Enterprise.
So it kept us from forming
a subspace field
for the warp drive?
That is correct.
Computer, who is this L. Brahms?
Doctor Leah Brahms.
Engineer.
Graduate
of the Daystrom Institute.
Theoretical Propulsion Group,
Galaxy-class starships.
Team seven, junior member.
Junior member?
Looks like she wrote the book
on propulsion.
Call up subspace design logs.
Select menu.
Visual records
or L. Brahms' voice entries.
Voice entries.
BRAHMS:
Theoretical propulsion logs.
Federation Starship Enterprise,
Galaxy class.
Heading: Subspace.
Author: Leah Brahms.
Geordi La Forge.
How you doing, Doc?
Specify program.
Yeah, down to work.
You're absolutely right.
I recommend we evacuate
and seal-off
all non-operational areas,
and group the families and crew
on the odd-numbered decks.
Proceed.
I'd also like to set up
an assembly area
for treating radiation symptoms
in case it's needed.
After the shields fall,
how long before fatal exposure?
30 minutes.
After that, there is
nothing that can be done.
RIKER:
Away team to Enterprise.
Captain, we may have
found something.
There's a file
of memory coils here.
They are identical to the coil
we found earlier, Captain.
The Captain's log, perhaps?
That's what we were thinking.
Mr. Data, are they
in working condition?
I believe so, sir.
We can enhance them
through the image processor
in the ship's computer.
Good. Return at once.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
Computer, generate
a cross-section image
of the dilithium crystal
chamber.
What about...
reorienting the crystal?
BRAHMS:
It is possible
to reorient the crystal.
The key lies in adjusting
the lattice structure direction.
This modification
will be integrated
into the next class starship.
Sorry, can't wait.
You and me, Leah,
we got just two hours
to figure this thing out.
( sighs )
You know what I need to do?
I need to get inside there.
I need to be able
to turn that thing inside out.
Computer, is there
a cross-section image
we can replicate on a holodeck?
Select menu:
Design specifications
or prototype schematic.
Prototype. Elaborate.
A development stage
prototype schematic
at Utopia Planitia,
Drafting Room 5
of the Mars Station,
Stardate 40174.
Perfect.
Recreate it in Holodeck Three.
Stay with me, Doc.
Ready, computer?
Holodeck Three program is ready.
Damn...
Right back where it all started.
Oh, this is incredible.
Leah, did you design this?
BRAHMS:
The dilithium crystal chamber
was designed at outpost
designated Seran-T-One
Stardate 40052.
Some of the Federation's
best engineering minds
participated in its development.
That's the visiting dignitary
talk.
What's the inside story?
Off the record.
COMPUTER:
Access denied.
Personal logs are restricted.
Great.
Another woman
who won't get personal with me
on the holodeck.
Leah, I want to find a way
to supplement the energy supply
to the ship and to the engines.
Could we alter
the matter/anti-matter paths?
BRAHMS:
Theoretically, yes.
The system should be able
to accept more reactants
at a faster rate of injection.
Well, this is your baby.
Show me which ones.
Computer, did I ask
for a simulation?
Affirmative.
You asked Dr. Brahms to show you
which system could accept
reactants at a faster rate.
By accessing available imagery
an adequate facsimile
was possible.
Hmm, I did do that, didn't I?
Okay, well,
it's good to see you, Leah.
Continue with your analysis.
Systems L-452 through L-575
will accept reactants
providing all other systems
are calibrated
to an equal factor.
Then, if we use multiple
injector streams
hitting more than one
crystal facet
we could do it.
We could hold our own.
Leah, you're beautiful.
La Forge to Picard.
Go ahead.
Captain, we've found a way
to extend the matter/anti-matter
energy supplies.
Well done, Mr. La Forge.
Geordi, can you give us enough
power to get us out of here?
Sorry, Commander, we haven't
addressed that one yet.
First priority was
to maintain the shields.
Acknowledged.
We'll get to work on it
right away, sir.
Pass my congratulations
to the rest of your team.
Thanks, Captain.
We're all smiles down here.
Captain, we've been
able to verify
that these coils are the logs
of the Promellian Captain
but most of them have decayed
and cannot be repaired.
RIKER:
Can you hear any playback
at all?
On most, there are
brief sections
which may yield
some information.
Well, do the best you can, Data.
Let's just hope we can
get the section we need.
PICARD:
Surely he must have logged
the cause of the ship's death.
What Captain wouldn't?
They were all found
in an open locker.
I don't think he was
too concerned with security.
452 through system L-575.
COMPUTER:
Adjustments to dilithium crystal
chamber complete.
Impact analysis, computer.
Warp energy has increased
14 percent.
Reactants per unit time
remaining steady.
Yes, all right!
( sighs )
Computer, do you have any...
you know, personality
on file for Dr. Brahms?
Starfleet personality profile
analysis, Stardate 40056.
Did she ever debate
at the intergalactic caucuses
on Chaya VII?
Doctor Brahms attended
Chaya VII caucuses
on the following stardates...
Never mind the dates.
Computer, if you add data
from all these sources
could you synthesize a true
representation of Dr. Brahms?
There would be
a 9.37 percent margin of error
in the interactive responses
from the facsimile.
I can live with that.
Do it.
Dr. Brahms?
Geordi, it's me, Leah.
Don't start calling me
"Dr. Brahms"
or I'll call you
"Commander La Forge."
Right.
Now, we've managed
to maintain energy
but we can't leave it
in this realignment forever
without burning out components,
so we need to move quickly.
Are you with me?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
GALEK SAR:
We have been stripped
of all propulsion
and our weapons are useless.
We cannot move
and we cannot fight.
The ship is being lashed
with lethal radiation
from the aceton assimilators
concealed
in the rubble surrounding...
Aceton assimilators?
Aceton assimilators are
primitive generators
which can drain power
from distant sources.
Generators...
It would not
be difficult
to modify them
to convert energy
into radiation.
The Menthars hide them
in floating debris
an unsuspecting ship flies in...
instant booby trap.
And now we're
supplying the devices
with the energy to kill us.
No, no, no.
Will you listen to me?
You can't boost
the warp power that way.
If you can just
increase the speed
of the parallel
subspace field processor
to gain a quicker
response time...
I want to give us enough power
to strengthen the shields
and barrel out of here
not blow us up.
This is my design
we're talking about.
I did the calculations myself.
I don't care if you built it
with your bare hands
out of an old Ferengi
cargo ship.
It's going to go...
( imitates explosion )
...and we're going
to go with it.
I am not used to having people
question my judgment.
And I'm not
used to dying.
Okay, look.
You worked in a lab
on a static model.
This is a working machine.
It's got tens of thousands
of light years on it.
True.
Damn right.
Listen.
We'd never be certain that
the circuit paths are sealed.
You're good.
Very good.
I know my ship--
inside and out.
Well, then you must know me
inside and out
'cause a lot of me is in here.
You know, I
always wished that
a chief engineer
could be present
when a ship
is being built.
That's what's wrong
with designers.
We never get out in space.
Well, you're there now.
RIKER:
Commander La Forge
to the Bridge.
On my way, Commander.
Don't go away.
I mean...
Computer, save program.
How many devices do we think
we're dealing with, Mr. Data?
To create this
radiation field
would take several
hundred thousand, sir.
They've been out there
a long time, Data.
There must have been
some deterioration.
There is no way to precisely
calculate that, Commander
but it is likely.
Is there
any indication
of a weakness
in a specific part of the field?
WORF:
Nothing substantial, Captain.
Of any kind?
Well, there is a .1 percent dip
in the strength
of the radiation field
at... 21 mark 8 by 42 mark 0.
I want that .1 percent.
I recommend we fire
directional phasers
at those coordinates.
LA FORGE:
We won't be able to maintain
energy reserves.
We might even lose
a few circuits
in the new configuration.
How critical will the losses be?
Not enough to shut down
our engines
but if we don't make it
I don't know
that I can hold the shields.
There is also the possibility
that the phasers will supply
the assimilators
with what they need most--
energy.
You know, I imagine
a very similar discussion
taking place
in our neighbor ship
over a thousand years ago.
Well, let's hope our decisions
are more successful
than theirs were.
Mr. La Forge, I want you
to return to Engineering
and continue with your efforts
without delay.
Mr. Worf...
prepare the phasers.
Phasers locked
on coordinates.
Fire.
Nothing.
WORF:
Radiation levels increasing.
Eight percent.
Ten percent.
DATA:
Energy reserves are
dropping rapidly, sir.
Damn you.
Wouldn't that increase
the output
of the subspace processors
to gain a quicker response time?
The processors can handle
the extra input.
Yeah, but how do we reconfigure?
COMPUTER:
Energy reserves reaching
critical stage.
Standard procedure requires
termination of all simulations.
Computer, override
standard procedure.
Override authority restricted.
What?
Computer!
LA FORGE:
The crystal lattice
is breaking down.
We'll have to pick up repairs
when we can reach a Starbase.
The optimist
of the group.
How long do we have shields
based on current
calculations?
Under two hours.
And the radiation field
has increased by 17 percent.
So, what impact will that have
on fatal exposure?
Down to 26 minutes.
If we resist, we die.
If we don't resist, we die.
Mr. La Forge, have we shut down
all non-essential energy usage?
Yes, sir.
In fact, I need
to get some back.
I'm running a program
on Holodeck Three.
For what purpose?
Well, I've gone back
to the beginning
to the earliest construction
entries of the Enterprise.
I've created a...
well, a propulsion
design model to assist me.
I believe we're making progress.
Computer, reinstate
Holodeck Three program.
Holodeck Three program
is reinstated.
Mr. La Forge, your best
suggestion in one hour.
Picard out.
Computer,
resume Holodeck Three program.
Enter when ready.
There isn't much time left.
Somehow, we have
to generate
enough energy
to get out of here.
but we've got
a booby trap
that eats energy
for breakfast.
How do we fool it, block it,
shut it down, anything?
Okay, we know that for every
move the Enterprise makes
there's a countermovement
by the energy field.
Can we use that
to our advantage somehow?
Maybe.
There must be
a time differential
between the force
and counterforce.
If we can just make quick
continuing adjustments
in the linkups before
the counterforce reacts
we might just be able
to move this bucket.
Yeah.
Yes!
Leah...
do you like Italian food?
Like it?
Wait till I make
you my fungilli.
Okay, fusion reactor uplink
to navigation processor.
Hmm, then we have to adjust
the vector processor
and the drive coils.
( growls )
This is impossible!
Mmm... mmm.
Don't do that.
I'm sorry.
I thought it
would feel good.
I don't want to feel
that good right now.
What time is it?
Coming up on 1600 hours.
Oh, God, what am I supposed
to tell the Captain?
It's possible
and yet it's not possible.
Everything we've done says
we can't adjust that fast
but if we could,
it might work.
I could do it.
Data couldn't even do it.
It will take 100, maybe 1,000
adjustments every second.
How are you going to do it?
It's humanly impossible.
I'm not human.
You, uh...
you mean the computer
could do it?
LA FORGE:
Captain.
Captain, this is, uh...
this is a holographic
simulation of one of
the propulsion experts
who designed the Enterprise
engines, Leah Brahms.
We... I've been examining
the force-counterforce
response times
trying to see if we could create
linkage at maximum power.
And?
There's a...
there's a chance we could
maneuver out of this trap
if we turn the ship over
to the computer.
What kind of a chance?
I don't know yet.
But we could program it and try
it out on a few simulated runs.
And this is the only way?
I think so, sir.
( door chimes )
Come.
Any word from La Forge?
He's come up with something
that may give us a chance
if we agree
to stay out of it.
He proposes to turn
total control of the ship
over to the computer
because it is capable
of making quicker adjustments
than any human being.
Computers have
always impressed me
with their ability
to take orders.
I'm not nearly as convinced
of their ability
to creatively give them.
You know, Number One
you missed something
not playing with model ships.
They were the source
of imaginary voyages
each holding a treasure
of adventures.
Manning the earliest spacecraft
flying an aeroplane
with only one propeller
to keep you in the sky.
Can you imagine that?
Now the machines are flying us.
COMPUTER:
End simulation.
Fatal exposure.
Computer, reduce
thrust levels
another four percent.
Adjust trajectory
angle to compensate.
Begin simulation again.
There you go.
We got out.
Repeat simulation.
Same levels.
COMPUTER:
End simulation.
Fatal exposure.
See? Same variables
only this time, the computer
didn't quite make it.
( alarm blaring )
COMPUTER:
Deflector shield failure.
Lethal radiation levels.
Fatal exposure in 26 minutes.
It might work, Geordi.
And it might not.
I can't ask Captain Picard
to turn the ship
over to a computer.
It's all we've got.
Picard to La Forge.
Captain
two minutes--
give me just two minutes.
There is another way, Captain.
Two minutes, please.
Two minutes, Mr. La Forge.
Picard out.
Geordi, there's no other way.
No, no, no, wait.
Listen, turn it
completely around.
Literally-- come at it
from the opposite direction.
God, it's so simple,
it might even work.
Okay.
Computer, new simulation.
Everything we've
tried to do has been
based on
overpowering the trap--
more energy, faster
adjustments--
but that's exactly
what we can't do
because that's what
we're supposed to do.
That's the booby trap.
The answer lies in our
own computer, the mind.
The best piece
of engineering
we'll ever need.
But didn't your researches
indicate
a thousand adjustments
per second will be required?
But not if we shut
everything off.
One blast of everything we've
got left for a microsecond
to beat the inertia, and
then we shut it all down
except for minimal life
support and two thrusters.
No impulse engines,
no computer.
One propeller, Captain?
COMPUTER:
Deflector shield failure.
Lethal radiation levels.
Fatal exposure in 12 minutes.
Have you analyzed
the risk factor?
The numbers say it's even money.
It's no better than turning it
over to the computer
but no worse either.
But I say forget the numbers.
There's no way the computer
can compensate for the human
factor-- the intuition
the experience.
And the wish to stay alive.
Make it so.
I've run the
simulations, Captain.
If you want,
I'll take the conn.
Thank you, Mr. La Forge,
but you've done your job.
Now I must do mine.
I relieve you, Mr. Crusher.
Yes, sir.
( bosun's whistle blows )
All hands,
this is Commander Riker.
We are about to engage impulse
engines for a short burst.
Inertial dampeners
are on manual.
They may not fully compensate
for the acceleration
so brace yourselves.
COMPUTER:
Deflector shield failure.
Lethal radiation levels...
Computer, discontinue
radiation warning
until further notice.
It's all yours, sir.
Thank you, Number One.
Firing impulse engines.
Impulse engines are down.
Shutting down all systems.
( equipment powering down )
Velocity is 135 meters
per second.
( console beeping )
We will be entering the debris
field in eight seconds.
Starboard thruster firing.
RIKER:
Coming to heading 340 mark 10.
DATA:
Thruster is off.
RIKER:
Captain, that large mass
to the port
may contain an assimilator.
DATA:
Port thruster is firing.
WORF:
No reaction
from the assimilator.
We made it
over the first hurdle.
( console beeping )
Sir, object to port.
DATA:
Port thruster is firing.
Sir, the gravitational
attraction
of the various masses
has reduced our velocity
by eight percent.
By my calculations
we no longer have
sufficient momentum
to clear the
debris field.
Thank you, Mr. Data.
The asteroid's gravitation
is drawing us closer.
Velocity is increasing.
DATA:
Velocity is still
increasing.
Now at 219 meters per second.
DATA:
Starboard aft thruster.
You have used the asteroid's
gravitational pull
as a slingshot.
Excellent.
We're out.
We got through.
You have the conn, Mr. Crusher.
Yes, sir.
PICARD:
Initiate full restart.
Put all systems back on line.
LA FORGE:
With pleasure, sir.
Number One, make sure
that booby trap
doesn't bother
anyone again.
Mr. Worf, ready
photon torpedoes.
Set to detonate on impact
with the Promellian vessel.
Aye, sir.
You know, I've always thought
that technology could solve
almost any problem.
It enhances the quality
of our lives.
Lets us travel
across the galaxy.
It even gave me
my vision.
But sometimes you just
have to turn it all off--
even the gypsy violins.
Violins?
Different program.
We made a good team.
Mmm.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe we can do it again
sometime.
Oh...
I'm with you every day, Geordi.
Every time you look
at this engine
you're looking at me.
Every time you touch it,
it's me.
Computer, exit holodeck.
End program.