( electrical static )
( winds howling )
(shouting )
Placing beam-out marker.
Return transport,
14 minutes, 40 seconds.
Is your view any better,
Geordi?
Not too bad, Commander.
A lot of charged
particle precipitation,
but I can compensate.
Communicators
are dysfunctional.
Tricorders?
Readings only found
within five meters.
Good thing we didn't
bring Data.
We'd be unscrambling
his circuits for a week.
Commander, picking up something
on the positron scan.
( thunderclap )
GEORDI:
Over here.
Some electrically
conductive objects.
Recognize those
markings, Worf?
Yes, sir.
Romulan.
What the hell
were they doing
in the Federation sector?
Picking up traces
of ultritium residue.
An explosive device
must've been used
to destroy the craft
after it crashed.
All right, let's spread
out, 25-meter radius.
Our window back
closes in 12 minutes.
Commander!
Commander Riker!
( grunting )
( screaming )
Four minutes
to beam-up.
Where is he?
Wait here.
( coughing )
( groaning )
Worf!
Commander Riker!
RIKER:
Geordi!
Worf!
Commander Riker!
Hold your position,
Mr. Worf.
Worf!
( sighs )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's log,
Stardate 43349.2.
An unidentified distress signal
has led to the discovery
of a crashed Romulan vessel
on the surface
of Galorndon Core,
a Federation planet.
We have recovered
one survivor.
But Lieutenant
Commander La Forge
did not report back
with the away team,
and is still missing.
Get him to sick bay.
Secure sick bay,
post a guard
in visual contact
at all times.
He's not going anywhere,
Lieutenant.
I'm sorry, Commander,
there's just no way
to lock in on
anything down there.
Keep trying, O'Brien.
The electrical storm's
creating thousands of ghosts.
Well, beam some of
those ghosts back.
One of them may be Geordi.
Permission to lead
another away team, sir.
Denied.
When we get another
window in the storms.
The crash site?
The Romulan craft
is a total loss.
There's nothing
there to salvage.
Unless you wanna
use tweezers.
No sign of others?
Well, you couldn't
see more than two meters
in front of yourself
down there.
That certainly is
the last place
one would expect
Romulan encroachment.
On the other hand,
Galorndon Core
would provide ideal cover
for the opening move
of a new offensive.
I doubt if they were
there for the climate.
BEVERLY: We thought it would
be like working on Vulcans.
But there are subtle
differences, too many of them.
Can you treat him?
He has cell damage
to vital areas.
He's going to need a transfusion
of compatible ribosomes
in order to recover.
I'm setting up a schedule to
test every member of the crew.
We can't use
the replicator?
BEVERLY:
The molecules are too complex.
Will he survive?
I can't answer that yet.
Well, let me put it in
another way-- will he survive
long enough to tell us what
he was doing down there?
Doctor, it's an important
consideration.
I can bring him around
for a few minutes.
But there is one
serious complication.
His brain waves indicate early
neural pathway degeneration.
Head injury?
There's no obvious
cranial trauma.
I'm guessing his exposure
to the magnetic fields
on the surface
were slowly breaking down
his synaptic
connections.
Will that affect
Geordi the same way?
( inhaling deeply )
BEVERLY: He'll be conscious
for a minute or two.
RIKER: You are on board the
Federation Starship Enterprise.
We're treating your injuries.
How long were you down
on Galorndon Core?
Do you understand me?
I will not answer questions.
We need to know if there are
other survivors on the surface.
I am alone.
I will not answer
any questions.
Do you have a mother ship
who should be advised
of your condition?
The only answer he wants to
give is that he was alone.
Which suggests
that he wasn't.
( grunting )
Something, anything
to cut through the storm,
some way to get a signal
through to him.
A neutrino pulse.
We could build a portable
neutrino source and send it
in a probe to the
planet's surface.
It'll act like a beacon.
DATA: A neutrino pulse would
send non-charged particles
back up through the atmosphere,
and would be detectable
by Geordi's visor.
He can show us that he's found
it by modifying the pulse.
Make it so.
Captain, I have
a new transmission
on a parallel frequency
to the distress call.
From the surface?
No, sir, from inside
the Romulan zone.
We should be able to
view the transmission.
On screen.
MALE VOICE:
Tomalak to Pi.
We have received your
distress signal.
Respond.
If you can hear me,
we are entering
the Neutral Zone now.
We will reach you in six hours.
Mr. Worf,
hail the Romulan vessel.
Hailing frequencies
open, sir.
Romulan vessel, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
The frequency is open, sir.
Commander Tomalak,
we have intercepted
your transmission.
You are not to enter
Federation space.
Captain Picard, my apologies.
Had I known you were
in this sector,
I certainly would have
advised you
before crossing
the Neutral Zone.
Indeed.
I'm sure you will
understand when I explain.
One of our ships had a slight
navigational error
and apparently crashed
on Galorndon Core.
A slight navigational error?
Nearly half a light year
past the Neutral Zone?
I assure you, Captain,
no aggression was intended.
Commander, we have recovered
one of your survivors.
He is on board your ship?
He is being treated
for severe injuries.
And his craft?
Destroyed,
deliberately...
after the crash.
I'm sure you are prepared
to leave at once
and rendezvous
with me in the Neutral Zone.
I have an away team
on the planet.
We are waiting for a window
in the storm to beam them up.
And then you will return
my officer?
Are there any other Romulans
we should be looking to
recover from Galorndon Core?
No, it was a one-man craft.
Captain, we will be
at the Federation border
of the Neutral Zone in
roughly five hours.
We will expect you to
rendezvous at that time.
Counselor?
There's great hostility
behind his smile.
He'll stop at nothing
to complete his mission.
Including the Neutral Zone
border.
Captain, I see no reason to
return the Romulan to his ship.
He should be held
and interrogated.
We have every right
to detain him, sir.
Without evidence of
intent, Number One,
it will not be
a simple matter.
It obviously wasn't
pilot's error.
I think it demands
a response from us.
But we must measure
our response carefully,
or history may remember
Galorndon Core
along with Pearl Harbor
and Station Salem-One
as the stage for a
bloody preamble to war.
I want him off all the drugs.
They're not doing anything.
Dr. Crusher to Picard.
PICARD:
Go ahead, doctor.
My patient is not responding
to treatment.
You haven't found
a compatible ribosome donor?
BEVERLY: The lab is still
processing the tests.
Early results indicate humans
have far too many
bio-rejection factors.
I've also ruled out the
Vulcans we've tested.
I think I'll try a little
old-fashioned country medicine,
keep the fever down, try to
let the body heal itself.
Keep me advised.
Picard out.
Captain, the neutrino
beacon is operational
and we've placed it
aboard a class 3 probe.
Well done, Ensign.
Mr. Worf, launch the probe.
Aye, aye, sir.
( howling winds and thunder )
( grunting )
( yelling )
( beeping )
Probe has reached
the surface, sir.
The neutrino stream
is coming in strongly.
Sensors are tracking the probe
despite the interference.
( panting )
LA FORGE: A stationary
neutrino source.
Wesley Crusher.
Thank you, Wesley.
( grunts )
You are my prisoner!
Right.
Congratulations.
Surely a strategic triumph
for the Romulan empire.
Stay there!
Shoes are getting
full of sand.
I just hate that,
don't you?
Name and rank.
Lieutenant Commander
Geordi La Forge.
I don't think I got yours.
A Romulan ship
will arrive shortly.
You will accompany me
on board.
I don't think so.
See, we heard your message,
too, and, well...
the fleet's in, Commodore.
Sky is full of
Federation ships.
You're lying.
I never lie when I've got sand
in my shoes, Commodore.
Get up.
Seriously...
the only way out of here
is for you to put
that thing down,
and soon as there's
a window in the storm...
( coughing )
GEORDI:
You okay?
( coughing )
You gotta be kidding.
Sit.
Welcome to Galorndon Core,
where no good deed
goes unpunished.
Yes, Doctor?
Lieutenant, good.
Come in.
Please, sit down.
We have finally found a
compatible ribosome match
for the Romulan,
but only one.
You.
That is impossible.
I am a Klingon.
Different species, yes.
But many humanoids have
comparable cell structures,
and you have what
this Romulan needs.
There's absolutely
no risk to you.
You did understand
that was the purpose
of all the testing?
I have no objection
to tests.
You have an objection
to being a donor.
Yes.
Lieutenant, I understand your
feelings about the Romulans,
but this is not the
time or the place--
If you had seen them
kill your parents,
you would understand, Doctor.
It is always the time and place
for those feelings.
This Romulan didn't murder
your parents,
and you are the only one
who can save his life.
Then he will die.
I sure wish you'd
put that away.
You're afraid of dying?
You bet I am.
Who isn't?
I'm not.
( scoffs )
Right.
To die in the service
of my people...?
Oh, the Romulan
path to glory.
You can be sarcastic now.
But in a few millennia,
when humans are extinct
and the Romulan empire
spans the galaxy...
You really believe that stuff,
don't you, Commodore?
You may address me
as Centurion Bochra.
Bochra.
Good, solid Romulan name.
( coughing )
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Wrong.
Your heart rate
just shot way up.
It translates a wide range of
radiation into neural impulses.
Allows me to see.
Without it, you're blind?
Yeah.
How did this happen?
( sighs )
I was born that way.
And your parents let you live?
What kind of
question is that?
Of course, they let me live.
No wonder
your race is weak.
You waste time and resources
on defective children.
Whoa.
Must be having some sort
of polarity shift.
The diagnostic insists
everything's fine.
( coughs )
Hey.
Hey, your body temperature
has gone up
almost another full point.
What are you saying?
I don't know, I...
It-- it must be this place.
It's all that
electromagnetic soup.
It's wreaking havoc on
our nervous systems.
Your metabolism's
messed up.
So is my interface
with the visor.
We gotta get out of here
while we still can--
Sit down!
Bochra...
( sighs )
( coughing )
What is that?
It's just a background
fluctuation, Commander.
He hasn't found it yet.
Then he must be
hurt... or dead.
When does our next
window open up, Mr. Data?
There's no indication,
Commander.
I have no way to predict.
Incoming Romulan
transmission, Captain.
They're early.
DATA: The Romulan
Warbird should still be
29 minutes away from the
edge of the Neutral Zone.
Close enough, however,
to see that we're not there.
( sighs )
On screen.
Picard, I'm approaching
the Federation border
and the Enterprise
is not to be found.
Why?
My away team is unable
to leave the surface
because of the storms.
TOMALAK:
And my officer?
He is alive.
His life remains in jeopardy?
Yes.
And yet you will
still not permit me
to cross into your precious
Federation space
to retrieve him?
If the point has not yet been
made clearly, Commander,
let me make it again.
Romulan warships
do not enter Federation space
unless they are prepared
to do battle.
But a mission of mercy?
A mission to recover one
of your officers
who has been caught
on a Federation planet...
for reasons as yet unknown.
TOMALAK:
I have already explained.
And I have rejected
your explanation!
Territories.
You would
measure territories
against a man's life?
Commander, I am
singularly impressed
by your concern
for a life.
Do not risk any more lives
by leaving the Neutral Zone.
Picard out.
Bochra.
Bochra, you're in bad shape.
And my vision's getting worse.
Now, there's a beacon
out there
that'll get us
back to my ship.
But not if I can't
find it.
I cannot surrender
to the Federation.
Then stay here and die.
If the situation were reversed,
would you not die
to avoid capture?
I don't know.
I might, if I thought
it was necessary,
if the stakes were high enough.
But they'd have to be
pretty damned high.
( scoffs )
I guess I'd make a pretty
lousy Romulan, huh?
( chuckles )
I no more wish to
die than you do.
Bochra...
there are times
when it's necessary
to die for one's ideals.
Do you believe
this is one of those times?
Come on.
Let's go find that beacon.
Whoa.
What is it?
Everything's gone blank.
I'm blind.
( door chimes )
Come.
Worf.
You are busy.
Forgive my intrusion.
For what it's worth,
I understand
your bitterness.
With respect, sir,
you cannot.
I am asked to give up the
very lifeblood of my mother
and my father to those
who murdered them.
So, you blame all
Romulans for that?
Yes.
Forever?
What if someday, the Federation
made peace with the Romulans?
Impossible.
That's what your people said
a few years ago about humans.
Think how many died
on both sides in that war.
Would you and I be
here now, like this,
if we hadn't been able to let
go of the anger and the blame?
Where does it end, Worf?
If that Romulan dies,
does his family
carry the bitterness
on another generation?
Then you believe I should.
What I believe
doesn't matter.
My Starfleet training
tells me one thing.
But everything
I am tells me another.
BEVERLY: Lieutenant Worf,
report to sick bay.
Acknowledged.
( shivering )
Lieutenant, his life
is coming to an end.
I thought it important
for you to see him again.
It's not too late to
change your mind.
Come close to me, Klingon.
Let me die with my hands
at your throat.
There is a substance
within my cells
which you need to survive.
Then you've come to hear me
beg for my life.
No.
I would rather die
than pollute my body
with Klingon filth.
I've lost almost all
feeling in my legs.
My synapses must be
turning to jelly.
The visor's fine,
I just can't see a thing.
How do we locate
the beacon?
We don't.
Do all humans
give up so easily?
Bochra, we're lost.
Unless you've got something
that can smell neutrinos.
We have the sensor device
you're carrying.
Tricorder.
It's not set up
to detect neutrinos.
Your eye device does.
Connect them.
That's crazy, they don't
speak the same language.
Besides, I'd never be able
to get an accurate sampling.
Wait a second.
Wait, I wouldn't need
an accurate sampling,
just a-- a pointer.
A neutrino Geiger counter.
( sighs )
It's still not possible.
You cannot do it.
Under normal circumstances,
maybe.
Here, no way.
Why?
Because I can't see!
Adapting the neural output pods
of the visor is tricky work.
It can't be done by touch.
Then I will be your eyes.
The storm is beginning
to subside, Captain.
We should have a window
in less than an hour.
There's still no indication
that he's found the beacon, sir.
Assemble an away team.
Yes, sir.
Captain, the Romulan warship has
crossed the Neutral Zone border.
It is in Federation space,
and heading towards us.
Belay that order,
Number One.
Red alert.
( alarm sounding )
GEORDI: Make sure the
scanner select limiter
matches the visor
output range.
BOCHRA:
Not so fast.
Now, place the
neural output pods
in contact with the tricorder
scanner heads.
Ready.
Let her rip.
( beeping )
Bearing 3-5-0.
( laughing )
We did it!
The first Federation-Romulan
co-venture.
The storm may be breaking.
With any luck, there'll be
an electromagnetic window
opening up, and we
can get out of here.
At which point,
I'll be your prisoner.
Can you walk?
I don't know.
Well, let's find out.
Come on.
Okay, let's go.
Straight ahead.
Okay.
To the right.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wish to see me, Captain?
Yes, Lieutenant.
I assume you know
what it's about.
Yes.
The Romulan vessel
will reach us within the hour.
If our patient dies,
it may be just the excuse
the Romulan Commander needs
to start an incident.
The death of a Romulan officer
at the hands of the Federation.
Think of it.
I have, Captain.
So, there is no question
that the Romulan officer
is more valuable to us
alive than dead.
I understand.
Lieutenant...
sometimes the moral
obligations of command
are less than clear.
I have to weigh the
good of the many
against the needs
of the individual,
and try to balance them as
realistically as possible.
God knows, I don't
always succeed.
I have not had cause
to complain, Captain.
Oh, Lieutenant,
you wouldn't complain
even if you had cause.
If you order me to agree
to the transfusion,
I will obey, of course.
I don't want to
order you...
but I ask you.
I... beg you...
to volunteer.
I cannot.
Lieutenant?
Sir?
That will be all.
Picard to Dr. Crusher.
BEVERLY:
Go ahead.
Do not continue to enlist
the cooperation
of Lieutenant Worf.
I won't have to,
Captain.
The Romulan has died.
( storm roaring )
BOCHRA:
We've found it!
GEORDI: Now, we have to
alter its signal pattern
so the Enterprise knows
we've found it.
Will that
be difficult?
No!
Not with your help.
Scanners are showing
a window, Captain.
Expected duration?
Nine minutes,
40 seconds, sir.
No change in the neutrino
beacon signal, sir.
Romulan ship
approaching.
Bearing 3-54,
mark 2-8-7.
On screen.
WORF:
Entering phaser range.
We are being hailed, sir.
On viewer.
You have one chance to
escape destruction, Picard.
Return my officer at once.
Commander, you have entered
Federation space
despite my warning.
You forced the situation!
I will not leave
without him.
He's dead.
Then he is but the first
to fall, Picard.
The Romulan ship
is routing power
to its forward
disruptor array.
All shields to maximum.
Aye, sir.
Lock phasers on target.
WORF:
Phasers locked and ready.
Captain, the signal pattern
from the beacon is modulating.
It's Geordi.
We can't transport him
with the shields up.
If we lower our shields,
the Romulan will strike.
The electromagnetic window
on the planet is closing, sir.
Three minutes remain.
Transporter room,
lock onto
the neutrino beam
and stand by.
O'BRIEN:
Standing by, Captain.
The window is allowing
intermittent sensor readings.
There's still numerous
ghost images,
but I believe
we are picking up
two life-forms near
the beacon.
Another Romulan?
I cannot say.
The electromagnetic interference
prevents an accurate reading.
But that's a likely
hypothesis, Number One.
If Commander La Forge has
located a second survivor...
Lieutenant,
hail the Romulan vessel.
Aye, sir.
They are ignoring our hail.
Repeat the hail,
all channels.
You say they have
no way of knowing
how accurate
our sensors are?
Put on your best
poker face, Number One.
Open a frequency.
Commander Tomalak.
It would appear our away team
has located a second man
from your one-man ship.
We're preparing to beam them
to the Enterprise.
After which, of course, we will
return the survivor to you.
No acknowledgement, sir.
Commander, both our ships
are ready to fight.
We have two extremely powerful
and destructive arsenals
at our command.
Our next actions will
have serious repercussions.
We have good reason to
mistrust one another,
but we have even better reason
to set those differences aside.
Now, of course, the question is:
who will take the initiative?
Who will make the first
gesture of trust?
The answer is, I will.
I must lower our shields
to beam those men up
from the planet surface.
Once the shields are down
you will, of course, have
the opportunity to fire on us.
If you do,
you will destroy
not only the Enterprise
and its crew,
but the cease-fire
that the Romulans
and the Federation now enjoy.
Lieutenant, lower the shields.
Leave the hailing frequency
open.
Yes, sir.
WORF:
Shields down.
Mr. O'Brien,
transport Commander La Forge
and the Romulan directly
to the bridge.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir. Energizing.
Security team
to the bridge.
Belay that order,
Lieutenant. Shields up.
No one is gonna harm you.
You have my word on that.
Well, Commander?
If he has been
in any way mistreated...
I have given them
no information, Commander,
but I have not
been mistreated.
In fact, this human
saved my life.
Tomalak, how is it possible
that you didn't know
of the second Romulan
on Galorndon Core?
A simple misunderstaing,
Captain Picard.
I was obviously misinformed
as to the size of the craft.
I assure you,
I intended no deception.
Of course not.
You doubt my good faith?
Let's just say my faith
would be strengthened
by a gesture from you--
such as powering down
your disruptors.
Disruptors powering down.
Thank you.
Cancel red alert,
Lieutenant.
Commander, we shall
return your officer
and escort your ship
to the Neutral Zone.
That is acceptable.
It's good to have
you back, Commander.
It's good to be back, sir.
Actually, I have
Centurion Bochra
to thank for it.
Indeed.
Commander La Forge
and Lieutenant Worf,
escort our guest to
Transporter Room One.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
Close call.
Too close, Number One.
Brinkmanship is
a dangerous game.