Computer, dispatches.
A research inquiry
from the Manitoba Journal
of Interplanetary Psychology
and three communiques
from your mother.
Transfer the letters from
my mother to the view screen.
And computer, I would like
a real chocolate sundae.
Define "real" in context,
please.
Real.
Not one of your
perfectly synthesized
ingeniously enhanced
imitations.
I would like
real chocolate ice cream,
real whipped cream...
This unit is programmed
to provide sources
of acceptable nutritional value.
Your request does not fall
within current guidelines.
Please indicate whether
you wish
to override
the specified program.
Listen--
PICARD:
Picard to Counselor Troi.
Now what?
Yes, Captain?
The pleasure of your company
is requested, Counselor.
We are, um... we're having
an little impromptu reception
for the arriving delegates.
Captain, I'm not really
dressed for a reception.
Oh, Counselor,
just throw on any old thing.
We're about to get
our first look at the wormhole.
Of course, Captain.
I'm on my way.
God forbid I should miss
my first look at the wormhole.
May I escort you,
Miss Troi?
Just tell me there's
some chocolate here.
PICARD:
Ah, Counselor Troi.
Will you allow me to do
the introductions?
This is Premier Bhavani
of Barzan.
Counselor Deanna Troi.
Your discovery has produced
a great deal of excitement,
Premier.
Hopefully it will
also produce
a new era of prosperity
for my people.
We'll see to that.
You know Mr. Mendoza,
the Federation negotiator.
A pleasure to see you again,
Counselor Troi.
This is a worthy Federation
competitor in the bidding,
Leyor of
the Caldonians.
Madam.
MAN:
And I am
Devinoni Ral.
Ship's Counselor,
Deanna Troi.
MENDOZA:
My good friend
Ral is
the best hired gun
in the business.
Hired gun?
My good friend Mendoza means
that I'm a negotiator
who serves
a variety of clients.
On this particular occasion,
I represent the Chrysalians.
BHAVANI: I believe it's almost
time, isn't it, Captain?
Indeed.
It will be visible
directly ahead.
Is it always on time,
Bhavani?
Always.
We see it every
233 minutes.
Our scientists say
it's due
to radiation buildup
in the accretion disk.
The visible burst
is very brief.
There it is, ladies
and gentlemen, the first
and only stable wormhole
known to exist.
It's yours,
for the right price.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's log,
Stardate 43385.6.
We are orbiting Barzan Two,
which is entertaining bids
for control of what appears
to be a stable wormhole,
which could provide
a permanent shortcut
to the distant
Gamma Quadrant.
As you all know,
the environment
on my planet
is completely inhospitable
to most other life-forms.
So I'd like to express
my appreciation
to you,
Captain Picard,
for hosting
these negotiations.
The Barzan has been
a society
dependent on others
for generations.
We want that to end.
The appearance of this stable
wormhole in our space
provides us with our first
true natural resource.
We have neither
the experience
nor the technology
to exploit it.
But you do.
RIKER:
Excuse me.
There's a delegation
of Ferengi
that wishes
to be beamed aboard, sir.
Were you expecting
the Ferengi, Premier?
No, but I do not wish
to create ill will, Captain.
If they are interested
in bidding,
I have no objection.
Chief O'Brien,
this is Captain Picard.
Will you beam
the Ferengi directly
to the observation lounge?
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir.
On behalf of all Ferengi,
I protest.
Why were we not invited
to these negotiations?
BHAVANI:
My apologies.
We did not anticipate
your interest.
You're welcome
to join us.
My name is DaiMon Goss.
And these are my consuls,
Kol and Dr. Arridor.
We'll need chairs.
I'm Captain Picard
of the Enterprise.
I am serving as host
for these proceedings.
Good, then see to it
we get some chairs.
Let me explain--
Fine, fine, just have
your Klingon servant
get us some chairs.
I'm in charge
of security.
Then who gets
the chairs?
DaiMon, due to
the delicate nature
of these negotiations,
all parties
have agreed that
one representative
will suffice. Now I will
be happy to provide
your consuls
with accommodations
and you may have
my chair.
Very well.
Premier.
( sighs )
Kol, the bag.
RIKER:
Gentlemen, this way.
We can handle all
the pleasantries later.
Now, let's get
down to business.
I'll match anyone's
best offer
and add the gold
on top of it.
( chuckling )
COMPUTER:
Devinoni Ral,
human, age 41.
Born Brussels,
European Alliance.
Relocated at age 19
to Hurkos Three.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Should I call
for an appointment?
No.
I was just looking
over some personnel files.
Well, that's too bad.
Thought you might
be thinking about me.
I thought you'd be deep
in negotiations by now.
In recess.
I never play the opening
rounds, anyway.
Inconsequential.
Besides, there are
much better things
to negotiate
on this ship...
like dinner tonight?
What about your
traveling companion?
My traveling companion
is... traveling.
I sent her home.
Why?
You know why.
Weren't you
getting along?
Don't do that.
What?
Don't do
"Counselor" Troi.
Was I?
Yes, you were.
When you leave
this office...
who are you?
Oh, so that's
how it goes.
You never do.
You never do...
leave...
the office.
What are--
Shh-shh-shh.
Dinner at 8:00?
The readings from the Barzans'
probe of the wormhole
are quite impressive,
Captain.
The wormhole
delivered the probe
beyond the Denkiri Arm
in the Gamma Quadrant.
( whistles )
It would take nearly
a century at warp 9
to cover
that distance.
The same distance could be
achieved in a matter of seconds
through the wormhole.
Mm.
Imagine the Ferengi, collecting
tolls if we lose to them.
I don't think
the Ferengi are
the greatest threat
at the table.
With all of
DaiMon Goss's bluster,
they don't have the resources
the Barzans need.
Mm-hmm. I think
that Devinoni
is the one that we need
to watch out for.
An accurate observation.
How did you
recognize that?
Well he was the most
comfortable one in the group.
You must play poker,
Commander.
Poker? Is that a game
of some sort?
Commander Riker conducts
master classes in poker.
Our skills are
not dissimilar, Commander.
Mr. Mendoza, if this
lives up to its billing,
it will be a discovery
of extraordinary value.
But it is
a very big "if."
a wormhole is there one moment
and then gone the next.
A stable wormhole
is unheard of.
Are you saying this
may not be what it seems?
The Barzans do not have
manned space travel,
so they had to resort to
an automated probe.
Its findings are limited.
It cannot be determined
from these charts
how stable
the wormhole really is,
or how long it will
remain intact.
The Federation
could end up buying
a proverbial lemon.
"Proverbial lemon"?
Later, data.
Aye, sir.
And of course,
that means
once the contract
is negotiated and closed,
we would be obliged
to fulfill the terms.
I think we should take a look
for ourselves.
I don't think Bhavani
could object to that.
Geordi has been in
continuous visual contact
with the wormhole,
Captain.
I think it's
a logical choice.
I would also like
to volunteer, sir.
Mm, nobody's going in there
until we have done
a full sensor
analysis.
I want to do everything possible
to determine
that it is safe,
and when I am satisfied
then you, Data,
and Commander La Forge
will enter the wormhole,
tomorrow.
Just a moment of discomfort
for a good cause, DaiMon.
You understand this
will not be lethal?
Doctor,
you surprise me.
I have no wish
to kill anyone.
A short-term crippling
will suffice.
Then, this will
be just fine.
A distillation of your
own blood pyrocytes--
harmless to you, undetectable
by the ship's bio-filters,
but when absorbed
through your victim's skin
it will provoke an extreme
allergic reaction.
I'd say it's time to extend
the hand of the Ferengi
to the representative
of the Federation.
Much better.
Thank you.
Come in for a drink?
Ah, Federation decor.
Not your style?
Well, conformity
is not my style.
What would you like?
I'd even like another.
Well, there she is again.
Counselor Troi.
I'm not.
Computer, champagne.
For two.
Am I moving
too fast for you?
No, I'm moving
too fast for me.
I like that better.
I haven't been able to stop
thinking about you all day.
You must have had
a nice day.
Anticipation is fun.
We'll be late
for dinner.
Very late.
Mr. Mendoza?
I seem to be
a bit warm.
I need some help here.
You attempt to gain
every unfair advantage, Picard.
Premier Bhavani
has no objection.
Well, I most
certainly do.
First, you conveniently
arrange to play host,
then you plan to send
a manned probe
into the wormhole.
The Federation thinks
it can do anything
it wants to.
Well I will not
tolerate it!
I will gladly share
the results
of our explorations
with all the delegates.
And you expect us to believe
what you report?
Then send in
your own probe, Goss.
That's exactly
what I intend to do.
And I should strongly suggest
that you stay out of our way!
Tell Data and La Forge
to do themselves a favor
and stay
out of their way.
CRUSHER:
Captain Picard,
please come to sick bay.
Acknowledged, Doctor.
CRUSHER:
Whatever he's got
is obviously not
life-threatening.
It's some kind of system-wide
histaminic reaction.
He certainly
can't go back
to negotiations
for several days.
Will you keep me
informed?
Mm.
The Federation's
top negotiator
taken out by
a mysterious ailment.
Suspicion?
With the Ferengi around?
Always.
You'll have to fill in,
Number One.
Me?
Well I am
the designated host.
It would be a most
awkward transition.
You're the next
likely choice.
And Mr. Mendoza
will certainly agree.
He's quite impressed
by your natural instincts.
Excuse me sir, but those
weren't natural instincts,
those were
poker instincts.
A card game doesn't exactly
prepare me for this.
Yes, the stakes
are higher.
But then,
isn't that when
the game gets interesting,
Commander?
The wormhole will reappear
in 30 seconds, sir.
WORF:
The Ferengi pod
is moving into position.
Shuttle nine,
stand by.
Ferengi pod, this is
Lieutenant Commander La Forge
in the Enterprise
shuttle.
This is Dr. Arridor.
Go ahead.
Would you care to take
the point, Doctor?
We will gladly yield
that honor to you,
Lieutenant Commander.
You know,
if this doesn't work,
the thought of spending
the rest of my life in here
is none too appealing.
There is a bright side,
Geordi.
You will have me
to talk to.
DATA:
It is visible, Captain.
Proceed when ready.
DATA:
...and intense energy fields
( audio distorting )
which appear to be stable--
They've traveled beyond our
communication capability, sir.
A complete analysis
of our bid is available
on the ship's computer
for your consideration.
Commander, I realize
what a difficult position
this must be for you.
If you don't
understand something,
I hope you won't be
too embarrassed to ask me.
I think I have an idea
what the rules are.
Well, that's what makes it
so interesting.
The rules of the game change
to fit the moment.
Not unlike commanding
a starship, Mr. Ral.
Well, Mr. Riker's
placed a--
a great deal
of emphasis on defense,
a subject he obviously
knows well
having served Starfleet
in a number of conflicts.
Now, the Chrysalians?
We're enemies
to no one...
and we choose
to remain that way.
Neutral.
Neutral, and uninvolved,
sir...
in virtually all interstellar
matters of consequence.
No one would claim that
the Chrysalians
are as powerful as
the mighty Federation.
But, we have resources,
and technology,
and scientists, too.
But we also have had peace
for ten generations.
RAL:
You know,
I was thinking...
TROI:
Mmm?
RAL:
Maybe I could stretch out
these negotiations
for a few days.
Would you like that?
TROI:
Mm-hmm.
Devinoni Ral...
who are you?
Well what do your Betazoid
senses tell you about me?
Not much.
My human physical response
must be blocking them out.
Good.
It never happened
to me before.
I rather like that
I'm more difficult to read
than your other men.
There aren't any others...
currently.
What about Commander Riker?
Who have you been
talking to?
No one.
No one, I just
sensed something
when I saw the two
of you together.
Will Riker and I
are good friends.
Uh-huh.
It was once a little more
than that.
Ah.
How come we're talking
about me instead of you?
Haven't you had enough people
talk about their lives to you?
Who counsels
the Counselor?
Oh, no.
I want to know about you.
I'm what you see
right now.
Just me... wanting to run
away with you,
but knowing you'd never leave
this damned ship.
When I first saw you,
I felt as if
I'd been waiting for you.
I'm trying to understand
why or how that's possible.
Does it matter?
Well, it will,
when I tell you.
But you must promise never to
tell anyone else.
What?
I am part Betazoid, too.
My mother was one-half.
I am one-quarter.
You're empathic?
The only one
of five children.
I must admit, I was--
I was never as comfortable
sensing emotions
as you seem to be.
So that's why
you left Earth?
Yes.
I've learned to live with it,
use it, as you have.
But, still...
it isolates us,
doesn't it?
And I thought
it always would,
so I tucked
my heart away.
I didn't need it.
I didn't want it.
At the negotiating table,
it can be fatal
to have a heart.
But I never realized
how much I needed mine...
until I looked at you.
I'm picking up an increase
in accretion matter
filtering in
from the terminus.
Monitors are functioning
normally again.
Ferengi pod...
everybody in one piece
over there?
ARRIDOR:
Our condition
is no concern of yours,
Enterprise shuttle .
We are competitors in this
venture, not partners.
Ferengi pod, out.
Yeah, happy landings
to you, too.
Curious.
Hmm?
We are not where
we are supposed to be.
What do you mean?
We're on the other side
of the wormhole,
aren't we?
According to
the Barzan probe,
we should be in
the Gamma Quadrant.
But these readings
clearly indicate
we are nearly 200
light years away
in sector 3556
of the Delta Quadrant.
Maybe the Barzan readings
were wrong.
Perhaps their readings
were correct.
Their probe could have
exited the wormhole
at a completely different
location.
Hmm, Data,
my visor's
picking up subatomic
fluctuations.
Meson and lepton activity
is definitely increasing.
Gravitational acceleration
is also increasing.
Something very strange
is happening to this wormhole.
Sorry.
You're unusually limber
this morning.
I'll say.
Devinoni Ral.
It's ridiculous
and wonderful.
I feel completely
out of control.
Happy, terrified.
But there's nothing
rational about this.
Who needs rational
when your toes curl up?
I'm afraid
I'm going to lose myself.
I can't get enough
of him.
Is it possible to fall
in love in one day?
I did.
It was like this
for you and Jack?
No, it was
another fellow.
I fell in love
in a day.
It lasted a week,
but what a week.
Then I met Jack.
Oh, it took months
to figure it out with him.
Well, then maybe
I should slow down.
Catch my breath.
Not let this thing get out of
control.
BOTH:
Nah.
( indistinct conversation )
To be honest,
I was surprised
to see the Caldonians
here at all, Leyor.
You must think Caldonia
very insular, Mr. Ral.
Oh no, no, not at all.
Not at all.
On the contrary,
I've always respected
your world's commitment
to pure research.
It's just that...
well...
Go on, please.
Well, scholars don't always
enjoy administrative demands.
And certainly
we've seen here
that the administration
of the wormhole is--
Yes, I must admit,
I have begun to feel
some trepidation about that.
Yes.
Yes, I'm sure
you have, Leyor.
I'm sure we all have.
Do you realize that
in the next century,
the number of ships
that will pass...
Gentlemen, this open session
is called by request
of the Caldonia
delegation.
Madame Bhavani,
Caldonia withdraws
from these proceedings.
For what reasons,
Leyor?
It has been made very clear
that the maintenance
and administrative requirements
are beyond our abilities.
Leyor, the Federation
would like
to negotiate
a trade agreement
in which we could acquire
your planet's rich deposits
of Trillium 323,
which we would add to our bid,
Premier Bhavani.
My apologies.
We have already reached
an agreement
with the Chrysalians.
Mr. Ral...
you either had
very good instincts
or a foreknowledge
of the Caldonian withdrawal.
Well, some people just don't
like to transact business
with the Federation,
Commander.
The Chrysalians
hereby add
the Caldonian Trillium 323
to its bid, Premier.
I'm telling you,
it's changing.
I can see it
with my visor.
I have no intention
of leaving yet.
We have not finished taking
our readings.
Listen, Doctor,
your readings must
be telling you
the same things
we're getting.
This is not
the Gamma Quadrant.
I will not confirm
your speculations.
This is not
a speculation, Doctor.
We are not where the Barzans
said we should be,
which would indicate this side
of the wormhole is not stable.
There are meson
and lepton fluctuations.
Local gravitational fields
are increasing exponentially.
Everything says we better get
the hell out of here.
It will be visible again
in 40 seconds.
We will make
our own judgments then.
I can see it now
and I'm telling you,
you don't have time to wait,
not even 40 seconds.
Ferengi pod, out.
Damn it, Arridor!
We're 70,000
light years
away from our ships.
Come on now!
Follow us in.
We'll lead you.
Idiots.
It's getting worse.
I'm taking us in, Data,
with or without them.
Thrusters at half power...
three-quarters...
Entering outer
event horizon.
They panic quickly
under pressure.
There...
precisely as scheduled,
right where
I expected it to be.
Everyone was talking today
about the way you absorbed
the Caldonian bid.
Well, the opening
was there.
I took it.
Commander Riker didn't know
how you managed it.
Let me tell you something
about Commander Riker.
He's good.
He's the most dangerous man
in that room to me.
But, he doesn't have
an edge...
your edge.
Our edge.
You make it sound
unethical.
Isn't it?
Deanna...
it's just business.
Why haven't you told anyone
you're an empath?
Because I find it makes
people uncomfortable.
I think you don't tell them
so you can gain an advantage.
Well I gained an advantage
by using it with you.
You didn't seem
to mind that.
Look, Deanna...
the point of negotiating
is to take advantage.
I don't know what the other side
is offering,
and they don't know
what I'm offering.
So we dance around each other
until somebody wins.
I never cry foul
when I lose.
But you're reading
their emotional states,
their inner selves,
and then using that
to manipulate them.
Well people have done that
for thousands of years,
just by listening
carefully,
by watching
body language.
I just happen
to be better at it.
You do it.
I do it to help my crew,
not outmaneuver them.
And I don't hide
that I'm an empath.
Oh, so you
announce it
to every alien culture
you encounter?
Or do you use it to give
your side an advantage?
Do you tell the Romulan
that's about to attack
that you sense that
he may be bluffing?
Or do you just tell it
to your captain?
That's different.
That's a matter
of protection.
Yes, protection.
Your protection,
your captain,
your crew, your edge.
Yes.
Now, it's a matter
of life and death
when you take
the advantage.
Me, I deal in property,
exchanges.
Nobody gets hurt.
So you tell me...
which one of us
would you say
has more of a problem
with ethics?
Excuse me.
May I join you,
Commander?
Bought out
the Ferengi yet, Ral?
Think I should
give it a try?
No, but I think that you will.
One way or another,
it's gonna come down
to you and me.
You know, you're very
good at this.
Very good.
Much better
than you realize.
Well, I hope I'm better
The last mile
of the marathon
is always
the toughest.
That's when the winners
are willing
to take the big risks.
You willing
to do that?
We'll see, won't we?
Well, let's see now.
I'm prepared to reach a firm
agreement with Bhavani
before we learn the outcome
of your probe's expedition.
Are you?
Oh, well, well, well.
That would not be
looked upon favorably
by the Federation,
I'd imagine.
You see, you have to
be willing
to take that
last step alone,
or it just isn't
worth playing.
Your point of view,
not mine.
Oh, I see that,
Commander, I see that.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be
second in command
of this starship.
You know, I feel
responsible for you
in a way... related.
Deanna.
We both love Deanna.
Oh, in different ways,
of course.
I will remove that burden
of responsibility right now.
My relationship with Deanna
stands very well on its own
without any help
from you.
Of course it does,
of course it does.
It's just that,
well...
she's a remarkable woman.
Brilliant, lovely...
very passionate.
And she could have
been yours, Will.
But you just didn't do enough
to keep her.
And now, well...
I'm here.
And I'm going
to take her, too.
That's the first bad play
I've seen you make.
If you can bring happiness
into Deanna's life,
nothing would
please me more.
You know you're not really
such a bad sort, Ral,
except you don't have
any values
beyond the value
of today's bid, that is.
Deanna is just the woman
to bring some meaning
to your sorry existence,
if you're smart enough
to take it.
I doubt that you are.
To the last mile.
Sir, the Ferengi vessel
is moving
out of orbit--
impulse power.
They are approaching the entry
to the wormhole, sir.
Computer, is the Ferengi Goss
still on board the Enterprise?
DaiMon Goss departed
the Enterprise at 1400 hours.
They are powering forward
missile launchers, sir.
Yellow alert.
Hail the Ferengi.
Request an explanation of
your actions, DaiMon Goss.
I have learned
from informed sources
that the Federation
has manipulated
these negotiations from
the very beginning,
and has already signed a secret
agreement with the Barzans.
That is not true.
The Ferengi offer was
never seriously considered.
Premier Bhavani welcomed you
to these proceedings
despite my better judgment.
We will be ignored
no longer.
They've fired a missile
directly at the opening, sir.
Destroy it.
On screen.
Firing phasers.
Your offers both
have merit, gentlemen.
If I could find
a deciding factor--
( alarm klaxon blaring )
Riker to Picard.
What's happening, Captain?
Goss has fired a missile
at the wormhole.
I need you on the bridge,
Number One.
Excuse me.
Excuse me for saying so under
the circumstances, Premier,
but this fight
seems to really be
between the Federation
and the Ferengi.
Now, it seems unconscionable
that your wormhole
is being used as a pawn
in their power struggle.
You must know we will not
allow you to do this.
If the Ferengi cannot have
the wormhole, no one will.
A missile will have
no destructive effect
on a wormhole.
But if it should explode
near the shuttlecraft,
they will be destroyed.
Casualties of war,
Captain.
My men are prepared to die.
Are yours?
Captain, he's lying.
I'm almost sure of it.
He doesn't mean what he says.
Why? What is he
doing it for, then?
( door whooshes open )
Permission to enter
the bridge, Captain.
Premier, with all
due respect--
Captain, I believe I am
in a better position
to settle this with DaiMon Goss
than you are.
May I address him?
Premier?
DaiMon Goss?
This is Devinoni Ral.
I have nothing
to say to you, Ral.
Well,
then just listen.
The planet Barzan
has reached an agreement
with the Chrysalians
for long-term control
of the wormhole.
Now, on behalf
of the Chrysalians,
I am prepared to offer
the Ferengi
free access to the wormhole in
perpetuity.
I have your word
on this?
Yes, my word, sir.
In exchange for Ferengi
convoy privileges
to be negotiated
in good faith.
This is an acceptable offer.
The Ferengi vessel has shut down
its forward missile launcher.
Stand down red alert.
Commander Riker...
I'm sorry you
had to learn about
my decision this way.
You represented
the Federation well.
But I have come
to believe
that the Chrysalian's
tradition of peace
is more desirable
to my planet.
Excuse me, Premier.
There's something
you should know.
I'm sorry, was there
something you wanted to say?
No, not at all.
I have sensed you suddenly
felt uncomfortable.
Well, after all, it was
a very tense situation.
But that's what's so odd.
It wasn't tense at all.
In fact,
I sensed no tension
from you or Goss.
Wha-- I--
I was tense!
I was ready to blow it up!
Wha-- I strongly protest!
Screen off.
It was as though
you were
performing a scene
for all of us.
Pardon me, Captain, I--
I believe there's a slight
conflict of interest here.
I agree entirely.
Mr. Ral asked me
not to tell anyone
he has empathic
powers,
which he uses to manipulate
his competitors
in a negotiation.
And, yes,
it did put me in
a conflict of interest,
which I hope
I have now resolved.
Premier, I believe Ral
has used your fear
of continuing aggression
between the Federation
and its enemies
to undermine
our position.
I also believe that
this incident
was staged by Ral and Goss
to provide you a reason
to choose in favor
of the Chrysalians.
Captain, it's
the shuttlecraft,
they're coming
back through.
GEORDI:
Shuttle Nine to Enterprise.
On screen.
This is shuttle Nine
reporting in.
Barely.
PICARD:
And the Ferengi pod, Commander?
Trapped on
the other side, sir.
In Delta Quadrant.
We tried to warn them.
They wouldn't follow us.
Elaborate.
Captain, this end of the
wormhole is currently stable,
but the other end apparently
shifts positions periodically.
The Barzan probe had no way
to recognize this.
Eventually, both sides
will be unstable.
GEORDI: It's a dry well,
Captain-- worthless.
Acknowledged, shuttle.
Main shuttle bay,
prepare for final approach.
MAN:
Aye, sir.
WORF: Captain, DaiMon Goss
is demanding
to know where
his men are.
Advise him to set
his coordinates
for the Delta Quadrant.
He may run into them
in 80 years or so.
Mr. Ral...
congratulations on winning
the rights
to the Barzan wormhole.
I take the risks,
Mr. Riker.
And I stand by
my agreements.
Come in.
When do you leave?
Soon.
I've been recalled
by the Chrysalians.
Explanations demanded,
and so forth.
I'm sorry.
Well, I've done well
for them over the years.
They understand the stakes.
It'll be fine.
I had to do it, Troi.
Bhavani was ready to go
with the Federation.
I sensed it.
I'd used up every card
in the deck.
I needed to change
the rules.
You must have known
I couldn't
allow you to do that.
My human physical response
must have been blocking
my Betazoid senses.
I'm very grateful for
what you did, in a way.
It's made me take
a hard look at who I am.
I don't like what I see.
I once asked you
to run away with me.
Now I'm asking again.
I need you.
You could help me change.
You could--
You could be
my conscience.
I already have a job
as Counselor.