Someone sure stripped
this place.
( clattering )
The reactor's gone.
No wonder they didn't answer
our hail for two days.
Nothing here
to answer with.
Commander, I am
detecting life signs
from behind that door.
Worf?
Commander, take a look at this.
Blood.
Yes, but not human.
I'm going to have to
do some analysis on it.
( grunting )
It's jammed.
( metallic scraping )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( tricorder pulsing )
The two scientists
are suffering
from phaser stuns.
I'd guess
several hits each.
Several?
It'll take us a while
to bring them around,
but they will recover.
We found a sample
of blood.
It's a rare
iron-copper composite
unique to one
humanoid species--
the Acamarians.
Acamarians?
Then that would suggest
the Gatherers.
It is a
likely hypothesis.
The nomadic marauders
who refer to themselves
as Gatherers
have raided other outposts
in neighboring sectors.
But they've never come out
this far before.
Mr. Crusher, set course
for the Acamar system.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43421.9:
In an effort to put an end
to the Gatherer raids,
we have come
to the Acamar system
to enlist the aid of Marouk,
the Sovereign of Acamar III.
PICARD:
Their raids have made
this sector unsafe.
They've ransacked
our research facilities,
our trade routes
have been disrupted.
The Gatherers
are elusive.
We've only managed to capture
a handful of them.
But with
the Starfleet's help...
Hunting them down
is not what I am proposing.
Reconciliation
with the Gatherers
is impossible.
It's been tried.
Every time
we've offered amnesty,
they've rejected it.
When was
the last attempt made?
Eighteen years ago.
Eighteen years?
For almost a century now,
they've been parasites
moving from star system
to star system,
living on what they could find
or steal.
They're still your people.
No. Captain...
you have to understand
our history.
A hundred years ago,
before the Gatherers split off
from our culture,
we were a savage, violent race.
Clans battled clans,
bloody, vengeful feuds
that lasted for generations,
but we overcame
those ways
all except
for the Gatherers.
After a century of wandering,
they may be ready to come home.
PICARD:
Despite your progress,
you are a divided society,
and so it will remain
until the Gatherers
return to Acamar.
The attempt may be futile.
But there is so much to gain
and there is so little to lose
by the effort.
This problem affects us all.
It cannot be ignored.
Sovereign Marouk,
welcome to the Bridge.
Thank you, Captain.
How soon will you be ready
to leave Acamar?
I'm ready now, Captain.
I need only bring aboard
two more servants.
I'll see to that,
and to your accommodations.
I have reason to believe
there is a Gatherer encampment
somewhere in the Hromi Cluster.
Mr. Data?
The Federation
has charted,
but not explored
several Class-M
planets in that area.
Any one of these
planets might serve
well as a base.
Mr. Crusher, set course
for the Hromi Cluster.
Aye, sir.
( beeping )
A fine ship, Commander.
RIKER:
We're all very
proud of her.
Yuta...
a light meal
in 20 minutes.
May I be shown
the kitchen, Commander?
You're the chef?
Yes, I'll prepare all meals
for the Sovereign
and her servants.
Well, we can provide
you with a kitchen,
but it won't really
be necessary.
These food dispensers
can synthesize anything
that you may need.
I'll show you.
Sovereign, may I offer you
a drink?
Yes, thank you.
Cold water.
Computer, a glass of water,
five degrees.
( beeping )
Please.
You're also the food taster?
That's part of
the cook's duties.
I'm sure the Sovereign
will wish to sample
many of the cuisines
your ship has to offer,
but there are some
Acamarian dishes
that she will
insist upon.
I will arrange
for a technician
to help program your recipes
into the computer.
Of course, I'll have
to try some of them.
What's your specialty?
I have none.
Don't be modest.
You can't tell me
you haven't come up
with a few culinary delights.
There is a spiced Parthasdish.
Parthas...
A green vegetable
with fleshy roots.
Parthas a la Yuta.
I look forward
to tasting it.
Sovereign.
Chef.
Now entering standard orbit
of Gamma Hromi II, sir.
Captain, I am detecting life
readings from the planet surface
as well as several
small areas of
thermal radiation
and carbon dioxide emissions
indicative of combustion.
Campfires, Data.
Is that not what I said?
It's worth a look.
Make it so.
Data.
Worf.
Artonian lasers.
Tonkian homing beacons.
Quite a collection.
DATA:
Noranium
alloy, sir.
Its salvage value
is quite low.
Looks like these Gatherers
weren't too discriminating
about what they steal.
WORF:
Commander.
( clanging )
Ambush!
Regalian phaser rifles, sir.
Not particularly powerful.
Powerful enough.
We came to talk!
Your words are wasted,
Commander.
They understand only this.
We're here to establish
a dialogue, Worf.
RIKER:
Data, tell me about noranium.
It vaporizes at...?
2,314 degrees, sir.
Of course,
noranium car...
Thank you, Data.
Setting seven
ought to do it.
( beeping )
Three, two, one...
now!
Enterprise,
four to beam up!
Cowards!
Your ambushes would be
more successful
if you bathed more often.
We've brought
the Sovereign of Acamar.
Marouk? Here?
With an offer of amnesty.
SOVEREIGN:
Full dispensation
will be extended
to all Gatherers who are willing
to return to Acamar III.
You don't trust me,
Marouk.
Should I?
But you expect me
to trust you.
Maybe you just
poisoned it yourself.
Taste this, Temarek.
( laughter )
( laughter continues )
Barbarians.
This is futile.
PICARD:
Sovereign...
Brull!
Go home, old woman.
You people haven't changed
in a hundred years!
You should know.
You were there.
Sit down!
Please.
Now, we're here to talk.
It's a waste
of time, Captain.
They don't care
about how they live.
Am I supposed to believe
that you care how we live?
Yes.
Brull, she's here, isn't she?
Maybe you forced her to come,
Picard.
Nobody forces me anywhere,
Brull.
What is there for us
on Acamar III?
A life, a home.
You can end your wanderings,
your miserable existence.
Do I look miserable to you?
( laughing )
The clan wars are over, Brull.
It is a past we're ashamed of.
It is why you had to leave.
Now... it is time to come home.
I want to speak privately
with Sovereign Marouk
and Picard.
Everyone else,
get out.
Any insights?
Brull's ready
to negotiate.
He just wants
privacy so that
he won't appear weak
in front of the
other Gatherers.
( mumbling )
( mumbling continues )
You are of the
clan Lornak.
What of it?
I-I've seen...
I've seen you before.
Yes.
But... but it's...
it's impossible.
No. Look closer.
I am Yuta, of the clan Tralesta.
( gasping in pain )
( raspy breathing )
I am the last of my line,
but my clan will outlive yours.
( raspy breathing )
( breathing stops )
Marouk's offer has value.
Commander!
But still,
I don't know.
But you'll agree
it is enough
to present to
your leader.
Chorgan is a better judge
of these matters.
I will take it to him.
You'll hear from me
in 20 days.
Brull, in 20 days,
I hope to be very far from here.
With all due respect, Brull,
I would like to make the offer
to Chorgan myself.
We'll gladly take you
with us on the Enterprise.
How many of your
men do you want
to accompany you?
I'll come alone.
If this is a trap...
Oh, it isn't.
Mallon, you'll be in charge
while I'm gone.
If I am not back in ten days...
TEMAREK:
Brull! Brull!
Volnath...
Away team to Enterprise.
Medical emergency.
Volnath was an old man.
There's nothing to be done.
There's a chance that
our doctors can do something.
You found him?
Yes, and there are no other
members of Lornak clan here,
so I claim his possessions.
Granted.
Have you no respect
for the dead?
What's there to respect
about a corpse?
( arguing )
( arguing continues )
BRULL:
Temarek, no!
He's been dead too long.
RIKER:
How?
Cardiac arrest.
You don't sound convinced.
No, he died of a heart attack,
all right,
but I can't find the cause.
His cardiac muscle is strong
and there's no sign
of arterial occlusion.
( doors open )
Brull, will you show Mr. Crusher
the course to set
to the Hromi Cluster?
A child?
This doesn't inspire
my confidence.
This is our
present position.
Set a heading for
3-4-3 mark 7-2.
That's going
to take us
through the center
of an asteroid belt.
Hey, what's the matter, kid?
Can't you fly yourself
around a couple of rocks?
Sure, I can, but if
we take this heading,
we can avoid the belt
completely
and only lose
12.1 minutes at warp 7.
Have it your way, kid.
For centuries,
my planet was in chaos.
Loyalty to one's clan
was absolute.
The slightest injury
to one member
demanded violent
retaliation.
And these blood feuds
could last for decades?
The obsession
with vengeance
would be passed
from generation to generation,
and with each act
of retribution,
the violence would escalate.
It's not unlike much of
the history of my own planet.
Your pardon, Sovereign.
May I be excused briefly?
Commander Riker requested
that I prepare him
an Acamarian dish.
Of course, Yuta.
Hey...
What are you doing?
Homework.
What is this?
Math.
I can see that, but
what does it mean?
This is the locally
Euclidean metrization
of a K-fold contravariant
Riemannian tensor field.
You any good at it?
You don't like me.
I didn't say that.
No problem.
I have many friends
that don't like me,
but what do you know about me?
You're a thief.
I steal to survive,
not because I enjoy it.
We Gatherers value our freedom.
We do what we want
and we answer to no creature.
Then why are you helping
Sovereign Marouk
to change all that?
Maybe because I want
something better
for me and for my children.
You have children?
Yeah.
Two sons.
One's just about your age.
He's not any good at math.
Parthas a la Yuta!
With the help
of one of your food stations.
It's wonderful.
Truly excellent.
Thank you.
Would you care
to join us?
I don't want to intrude.
You're not.
I was just leaving anyway.
Please sit down.
It really is delicious.
I'm glad it pleases you,
Commander.
I'm not your Commander.
My name is William.
I will call you William,
if you prefer.
I do. When you say "Commander,"
you say it like you say
"Sovereign" to Marouk.
As a servant.
You're an excellent Commander,
but you'd make a poor Sovereign.
Why's that? Not that I disagree.
You're not comfortable
with servants.
No, I prefer the company
of equals.
So you treat me as an equal.
And you're not comfortable
with that?
I'm not used to it.
I've always been a servant.
Not that I'm complaining.
The Sovereign treats me well.
I have all
that I could want.
What about freedom?
I can never have that.
Because you're the property
of the Sovereign?
No, I'm not her slave.
I can leave whenever I wish.
But you have no place to go?
Just the opposite.
My path is all too clear.
Yuta, you're an excellent chef,
but you speak in riddles.
I've never been very good
at conversation.
SOVEREIGN:
Yuta?
I believe the Sovereign
wants me to return.
Enjoy the Parthas.
BEVERLY:
Sick Bay to Commander Riker.
I've discovered something
interesting, Will.
On my way.
You're scowling, Doctor.
I'm thinking.
And?
The old Gatherer
on the planet?
I know what caused
his heart attack.
The medical tricorder
almost missed it,
but there was a microvirus
in his body
blocking his autonomic
nerve impulses.
And that stopped
his heart?
But here's the really
interesting part.
This microvirus will
only attach itself
to cells with a very specific
DNA sequence.
How specific?
Without knowing more
about their genetic makeup,
I can't be sure, but my guess is
this virus would only kill
one Acamarian in a million.
Pretty single-minded bug.
Too single-minded.
I can't believe
it's a naturally
occurring virus.
Meaning someone engineered it?
Meaning Volnath was murdered.
( sighing )
( communications beep )
DATA:
Commander Riker,
Acamar III has agreed
to your request for access
to their databases.
They are now being transmitted
into our computer
over subspace link.
Good.
Notify Dr. Crusher
when Acamar's medical database
is online.
Riker out.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'm disturbing you.
Not at all.
As...
the Sovereign has
no further need
for my services
this evening,
she suggested I
might spend some
time with you.
What a charming suggestion.
She appreciates the...
affection you've shown me.
Was I that obvious?
Yes.
Well, I've already dined.
Maybe you know
a good Acamarian dessert recipe.
Does that not please you?
Tell me what you want, William.
I will do anything you wish.
Wait a minute.
I don't understand.
Don't you want me
to give you pleasure?
Not as a servant.
I told you, I prefer equals.
Even in the matters of love?
Especially in matters of love.
I've offended you.
No, I only want to make you
as happy as you want to make me.
You're entitled to that.
No.
I'm not.
Yuta...
I do not feel
pleasure or passion.
I haven't been able
to for a long time.
I don't know
who did this to you
or why,
but it can change.
I wish it could.
Tonight most of all.
I'm sorry.
( red alert alarm )
( weapons fire )
( gasping )
Your people
have prepared
a warm welcome.
That's Chorgan's ship.
Shields holding.
Mr. Worf,
contact Chorgan.
Tell him Brull has brought us
to talk.
Chorgan is not responding.
Mr. Worf, can we knock
out their shields
without seriously
damaging their ship?
I believe we can, sir.
Prepare phasers
and open a channel.
WORF:
Phasers locked.
Channel open.
Chorgan, this is
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
All right.
Let's focus their attention.
Mr. Worf, fire phasers.
Their forward shields
are inoperative.
Well done, Lieutenant.
( communications beep )
We are being hailed, sir.
That's better.
On screen.
Brull, you traitor!
You have led them here
to destroy me!
Chorgan, if I had
wanted you destroyed,
you would not
be talking to me now.
Obviously,
I wanted something else.
And what is that?
I have onboard
Sovereign Marouk
of Acamar III.
I want you to hear what
she and Brull have to say.
She's worth
listening to.
I don't wish to listen
to either of you.
You have no choice.
Prepare to receive us.
We are beaming onboard.
Picard out.
Cancel red alert.
Tell Sovereign Marouk
to meet me in
Transporter Three.
Aye, sir.
You're going alone, Captain?
The danger is
minimal, Number One.
Chorgan is unlikely
to do anything rash
with the Enterprise's
phasers trained on his ship.
There are still risks.
For these negotiations
to succeed,
I must be a mediator,
not an enforcer.
You have the
Bridge, Number One.
Brull.
Chorgan.
This is Sovereign Marouk.
You may sit.
Chorgan, I think you will
find Marouk's proposal...
You know, Picard...
I could take you prisoner.
Oh, don't worry.
I've no intention of doing so.
I know what trouble it's been
for you to get here
and I am curious why.
Then let's proceed.
Quite simply, I'm proposing
amnesty for every Gatherer.
Amnesty?!
You mean slavery.
BRULL:
Chorgan,
if you want to know
what I think...
I don't.
Say what you
came to say,
but I doubt I'm going
to believe you.
I didn't believe this very
persuasive Federation Captain
when he suggested
we could reconcile
our differences.
I'm convinced now
it is the right thing.
Not just for you,
but for us, too.
We need you back.
I've brought
some Acamarian brandy.
I'm sure it's been a long time.
Hmm...
No.
You have spent a
century hunting us down.
She is trying to put an end
to all that.
Yes, and luring
us back
and putting us
in prison.
No, by accepting you back
as free men.
Will you feed us
and clothe us, too?
No, of course I won't.
What I will do
is give you the means
to feed and clothe yourself.
We've set aside some land
and you can use it to...
( laughing )
Land?
Do we look like farmers to you?
Then don't farm.
Use the land as you wish;
it's yours.
And the moment
you set foot on it,
you'll be better off
than you are today.
You won't be running any longer.
We will need autonomy.
Autonomy?!
PICARD:
Sovereign,
if we can
at least acknowledge
that Chorgan appears willing
to discuss your offer...
There are many levels
of autonomy.
Certainly your region
would have certain rights.
Yes.
And those rights
will be spelled out
before I agree to anything.
Commander, I am afraid
the only entry
we have on Volnath
in the Acamarian database
is a birth record.
Probably one of the last
of the Gatherers
to be born on their planet.
( doors open )
Commander, I've been digging
through the medical database
from Acamar III for hours
and I have found another victim
of the same microvirus
that killed Volnath
but only one-- 53 years ago--
a gatherer named Penthor-Mul.
Data,
anything in your file
on Penthor-Mul?
Yes, sir.
He was a member
of the Lornak clan.
He was captured
while leading a Gatherer raid
on an Acamarian outpost.
He died of a heart attack
before his trial ended.
Display Volnath's
birth record again.
Lornak... the same clan.
The only two recorded deaths
by this microvirus--
both from the same clan.
What does that tell us, Doctor?
If these microbes
were engineered for murder,
I'd say somebody could be
going after a whole family.
DATA:
Commander,
Chorgan, the present leader
of the Gatherers,
is also from the Lornak clan.
I want to know
how this clan was involved
with the Acamarian blood feuds
and I'd like to know any clue
as to who their enemies were.
How could this virus
have been transmitted, Doctor?
More ways than I can count.
And it's perfectly safe
to the carrier
as long as he doesn't have
the same DNA patterns.
Tailor-made for their enemies.
Commander, 80 years ago
the Lornaks massacred
a rival clan, the Tralestas.
It ended a feud
that had lasted for 200 years.
Ended it?
According to
these records,
there were no survivors.
The Tralestas were annihilated.
BEVERLY:
Something tells me
they weren't all wiped out.
There must be
a missing link here.
Computer, any members
of the Acamarian delegation
from the Tralesta clan?
Clan affiliation
is not within provided records.
Sir, I believe I have found
a correlation
between the two deaths--
your "missing link."
DATA:
That is Penthor-Mul
being led from his trial.
I don't see
the connection.
Behind him and to the left, sir.
Computer, scan
left and magnify.
The computer can extrapolate
and reconstruct the rest
of the face, sir.
Do it.
But that photograph
was taken over 50 years ago.
Fifty-three years ago
and she hasn't aged a day.
Three seats
on the ruling council?!
If we're going to be subject
to your law,
we want a part in making it.
Well, I agree you're entitled
to representation,
but not on the ruling council.
Unacceptable.
The real power
is in the council.
You're shutting us off already.
No, you're trying
to take too much.
No group has three seats
on the council.
I don't care what others have.
You only care
about what you can take!
Sovereign,
if the situation were reversed,
I'm sure you would be demanding
equal levels of representation.
You're right, Captain.
I apologize for my temper.
Perhaps a brief pause
would be helpful.
I agree.
Hmm...
Maybe a little touch
of that brandy?
Yuta.
PICARD:
You know--
thank you-- it is remarkable
how very much alike
the two of you actually are.
CHORGAN:
That's ridiculous.
SOVEREIGN:
Really, Captain.
No, I'm quite serious.
You are both
able negotiators,
strong leaders.
We don't obey
weak leaders.
We have nothing
in common at all.
We haven't agreed
to anything.
You're wrong, Chorgan.
You have agreed
to have some brandy together.
RIKER:
Don't move.
A Federation trap.
Chorgan, I assure you
my First Officer
has a very good reason
for his actions.
You do, Number One?
Yuta, move away
from Chorgan.
Do it.
Why?
Because of a man you once knew
named Penthor-Mul.
Penthor-Mul?
How do you know Penthor-Mul?
Tell him, Yuta.
I don't understand.
You were with
Penthor-Mul
when he died.
It was 50 years ago.
How could I...?
I know, Yuta.
Stop.
Chorgan...
keep perfectly still.
Your life
is in danger.
Step back, Yuta.
William, this is
not your concern.
It is now.
You're about to commit a murder.
It isn't murder.
It's justice.
Who are you?
Yuta of the clan Tralesta.
There-there are
no more Tralestas.
Five survived
the last Lornak raid,
but on that day,
a century ago,
my life ended
and my search began.
I was the one chosen,
transformed.
My cells were altered
and my aging slowed
enough to finish my task.
SOVEREIGN:
You used me
in order to get to the last few
you couldn't reach.
Yes, Sovereign.
You will never
leave this ship alive.
You're the last.
Once you're dead, what happens
to me doesn't matter.
The wars are over, Yuta.
You cannot understand.
RIKER:
You're right,
I can't
because I've seen
the part of you
that regrets
what you've become.
Listen to me.
You don't have
to do this anymore.
I have no choice.
You do.
William, I...
I'm sorry.
Stop!
( gasping )
( adjusts setting )
Yuta...
Don't do this.
Commander, I am
in your debt.
Oh, yes, thank you.
CREWMAN:
Hello, sir.
New orders
from Starfleet.
The rendezvous--
nothing, thank you--
the rendezvous
with the Goddard
has been postponed.
In the meantime?
Starbase 343.
We are to take on
medical supplies
for the Alpha Leonis system.
Sounds pretty routine.
Well, with the Gatherer truce
in effect,
it certainly should be.
Oh... we won't require
a full ship's complement.
I'm going to extend
shore leave on the Starbase
to anyone who wants it.
I'll pass that along
to the crew, Captain.