( rooster crows )
Brother John Bates,
is that not the morning
which breaks yonder?
I think it be.
But we have
no great cause
to desire
the approach of day.
( rooster crows )
Who's there?!
A friend.
Under what Captain
serve you?
Under Sir Thomas Erpingham.
I pray you
what thinks he
of our estate?
Even as men wrecked upon a sand
that look to be washed off
at the next tide.
He hath not told
his thought to the king?
No.
Nor it is not meet he should.
For though I speak it to you
I think the king is...
but a man, as I am.
The violet
smells to him
as it doth to me.
In his nakedness,
he appears but a man.
Therefore his fears,
out of doubt
be of the same
relish as ours are.
Yet, no man should possess him
with any appearance of fear
lest he, by showing it,
should dishearten his army.
He may show
what outward courage he will
but I believe,
as cold a night as 'tis
he could wish himself in Thames
up to the neck.
Methinks I could not
die anyplace so contented
as in the king's company.
His cause being just
and his quarrel honorable.
That's more than we know.
Or more than we
should seek after.
If his cause be wrong,
our obedience to the king
wipes the crime of it out of us.
But if the cause be not good,
the king, himself, have
a heavy reckoning to make
when all those legs and arms and
heads chopped off in a battle
shall join together
at the latter day and cry all
"We died at such a place."
The king is not bound to answer
the particular endings
of his soldiers,
the father of his son,
nor the master
of his servant.
Splendid, Data, splendid.
You're getting
better and better.
Freeze program.
Thank you, sir.
I plan to study
the performances
of Olivier,
Branagh, Shapiro
and Kullnark.
Data...
( sighs )
You're here to learn
about the human condition.
And there is no better way
of doing that
than by embracing Shakespeare.
But... you must discover it
through your own performance,
not by imitating others.
Riker to Picard.
Sorry to interrupt, sir.
Go ahead, Number One.
Sensors are picking up
a unidentified craft
in the Neutral Zone.
It's heading toward
Federation space.
We're on our way.
Picard out.
We'll get to the rest of the act
another time, Data.
Computer, file program
and clear.
Captain, why should a king
wish to pass
as a commoner?
If he is the leader,
should he not
be leading?
Listen to what
Shakespeare
is telling you
about the man, Data.
A king who had true
feeling for his soldiers
would wish to share
their fears with them
on the eve of battle.
Sir, will I be able
to schedule
a performance for the crew
in the near future?
Let's not rush
it, shall we?
Hmm.
Outpost Sierra VI
confirms our readings, sir.
They identify it
as a Romulan scoutship.
Bearing: 270 mark 14.
Scoutship.
What would a scoutship be doing
this far into the Neutral Zone?
Captain, shall
we transmit
a warning to withdraw, sir?
Open a hailing frequency.
Aye, sir.
Captain, the Romulan
is hailing us.
Visual.
Not within
range, yet.
Open a channel.
Federation ship,
do you read?
I require urgent assistance.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS...
Federation ship,
please help me.
Requesting asylum.
Under pursuit.
Pursuit?
Visual range.
On screen, Captain.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Red Alert.
Open a channel to the warship.
Come to intercept course.
Keep us out
of the Neutral Zone.
Channel is open.
How long before they cross over
into Federation territory?
41 seconds, sir.
Romulan warbird,
this is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation vessel
Enterprise.
You have crossed
into the Neutral Zone
and are engaged
in hostile action.
Explain yourself
and your intent.
No reply, sir.
Hail the scout.
Responding.
On screen.
Federation craft...
please, you must help me!
We are moving to intercept.
Maintain your course and power.
The scoutship
is severely damaged, sir.
Engines inoperative,
shields are down.
Position?
Coordinates 140 by 205, sir.
Federation space.
Right. Move to within
five kilometers.
Mr. La Forge,
prepare to extend
our shields
around the Romulan scoutship.
At that range, the shields
won't be able to take
much punishment, Captain.
Five kilometers, sir.
All stop.
Extend shields.
LA FORGE:
Shields in place.
We've got the scoutship,
Captain.
The weapons on
the warbird are
fully powered, sir.
Lock phasers.
Open a channel.
Ready.
Romulan vessel
you are now
in Federation territory.
Unless you withdraw...
No argument?
Warbird has re-entered
the Neutral Zone.
Heading
toward Romulan territory.
Massive power failure
to the scoutship, sir.
All systems are
going off-line
including
life-support.
Transporter 2,
prepare to beam
the occupant of the scoutship
directly aboard.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf.
Mr. Data,
lock onto the scoutship.
Take it in tow.
Energize.
I must see your Captain
immediately.
We'll get you
to Sick Bay.
After that...
This cannot wait!
I have information
vital to your survival.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43462.5.
We have beamed aboard
an apparent Romulan defector
who claims to be a low-ranking
logistics officer
with extraordinary information
about a secret offensive.
The humiliating defeat
at the battle of Cheron
has not been forgotten.
The new leaders have vowed
to disregard the treaty
and claim the
Neutral Zone.
Nelvana III is just
the first step.
You're saying an entire base
has already been
established there?
Within 48 hours,
the reactor core
will be on-line.
So the Federation sensors
that monitor the Neutral Zone
just missed it.
It would seem so.
In two days
a fleet of Romulan warbirds
will be within
striking distance
of 15 Federation sectors.
The Federation
will not permit that.
Then it is war that we're
talking about, isn't it?
Destroy the base now
and the threat is over.
Well, I'm sure you are fatigued
by your ordeal
and you require
medical attention.
Lieutenant Worf
will you conduct Sublieutenant
Setal to the Sick Bay?
We will attend
to your quarters.
No doubt you will wish
to question me further.
No doubt.
He tells a hell of a story.
You don't
believe it?
Well, the Empire knows
that we would never allow them
to build a base
within the Neutral Zone.
Commander, that would not be
an atypical Romulan ploy.
In their long
history of war
the Romulans have
rarely attacked first.
They prefer to test
their enemy's resolve.
RIKER:
I think he's a plant
to draw us
into the Neutral Zone.
That way, we look like
the aggressors.
And the Romulans would have
a legitimate excuse
for responding in force.
Exactly.
DATA:
That would also
not be an atypical
Romulan ploy, sir.
It's always a game
of chess with
them, isn't it?
Well, at least
he's given us
a chance to get a look
at some Romulan
technology close-up.
Mr. La Forge, you will
lead the away team
over to the scout.
Commander, you
and Counselor Troi
will conduct Setal's
interrogation.
Captain, permission to
observe the interrogation.
No, Mr. Data.
I need you
on the bridge with me.
There is much to be done.
We have less than 48 hours
to prevent a war
or, perhaps...
to start one.
This will depend
on establishing the truth...
I set
the autodestruct sequencer
before I left the ship.
Why?
Wouldn't you?
To prevent your ship
from being captured?
Excuse me for being
a little confused, Setal
but I thought
you were defecting.
I am not a traitor.
All you can see is
the opportunity to exploit me.
The Federation credo--
exploitation!
Oh, you couldn't get aboard
my ship fast enough, hmm?
Strip it down.
"What secrets might it reveal
that we can use?"
You're shortsighted people.
Can't you understand?
I came to stop a war.
If you could
just hold still.
With your metabolism
this will heal
in a few moments.
Thank you, Doctor.
How fortunate
that you know something
of Romulan medicine.
Yes, I had a chance to gain
some experience
recently.
Oh, yes.
The incident at
the Galorndon Core.
The two officers.
You are aware of a great deal
for a logistics clerk.
It was common knowledge.
I could show you
my rating code.
Forged credentials are
a simple matter for a spy.
How do you allow
Klingon pahtk
to walk around
in a Starfleet uniform?
You are lucky
this is not a Klingon ship.
We know how to
deal with spies.
Remove this tohzah
from my sight.
Your knowledge
of Klingon curses
is impressive,
but, as a Romulan might say,
only a veruul would use
such language
in public.
Mr. Worf please see
to the security arrangements
for our guest's stay.
Aye, sir.
( laughs )
You find something
amusing?
Lieutenant Worf--
I like him.
To be more accurate,
I understand him--
a warrior, proud,
fearless, living only
for combat.
Exactly the type
that will get us all killed
if we're not careful.
This is the
food station.
You can reach me
through the com panel.
Later, we would like
to ask you
a few more questions.
Computer, water.
Temperature?
12 onkians.
This system is calibrated
to the Celsius metric system.
Any temperature at all
on the cold side
of whatever your system is.
( food station beeping )
DATA:
There is no
unusual activity
in the Nelvana
system, sir.
Let's isolate
and magnify that system.
Nothing on
the sensors.
It's hard to believe
in what one cannot see,
and yet, conceivably
with their
cloaking technology
a fleet
of Romulan warbirds
could be passing
before our eyes.
There must be some way
to neutralize this advantage.
COMPUTER:
Captain Picard, priority one
message from Starfleet
coming in on secured channel.
In my ready room.
Computer, delay time?
Two hours, 22 minute delay
from time of transmission
at Starfleet Command on Lya III.
Computer, key access
412 mark 80.
Picard, Jean-Luc.
Starfleet priority code Gamma.
Decode.
Begin message.
Captain, we have received
an official protest
from the Romulan Empire
demanding the return
of your defector.
Obviously, we are
refusing to comply.
I join in your skepticism,
but if it is a deception
the Romulans are certainly
making a good show of it.
The Federation Council has
convened an emergency session.
There is no doubt in my mind
that this will eventually fall
on your shoulders, Jean-Luc.
You've got him.
You must decide
if he's telling the truth.
For now, I suggest you proceed
along the Neutral Zone border
toward a Federation position
proximate to Nelvana III.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Yes, Captain.
Please come to my ready room.
Aye, sir.
On my way.
LA FORGE:
Slow playback.
Display engine logs
and power data
for both vessels.
Now, watch what happens
at 095433 on the clock.
The scout has sustained
engine damage
forcing him to slow
to .615 impulse power.
The warship should overtake
him, but it doesn't.
Now, just 2.6 seconds later,
the warship slows
to precisely the same speed.
Three times, three
speed fluctuations.
The warship kept its
distance every time.
I don't think they
wanted to catch up.
And yet they fired
on the scoutship.
They could have
killed him.
Not necessarily, Doctor.
The Romulans have
the same capability
to direct the impact
of their weapons as we do.
Hmm. Is there
a possibility
the wound could be
self-inflicted?
They're very bad burns.
I hardly think...
A possibility.
Yes.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43463.7.
We are holding a position
at the Neutral Zone border
proximate to Nelvana III.
If our guest is telling the
truth, there are 21 hours left
before the Romulan base
becomes functional.
The Monitor and the Hood
are headed in your direction,
but they will arrive too late
to be of assistance.
Warnings have gone out
to all outposts along the border
as well as several independent
vessels in nearby sectors.
No one here wants a war,
Captain,
but we are prepared
to take them on
if that is what they want.
All Federation starships
have been placed
on Yellow Alert.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to
see me, Captain?
Yes, Data, I want you
to prepare a class-1 probe.
Set the sensors
for maximum scan.
I want every meter
of Nelvana III monitored.
I will start my calibrations,
sir.
Data...
Is there something else
you require of me, Captain?
Your clarity of thought.
Your objectivity, as always.
Sit down.
Data, it's very possible
that we are about to go to war.
The repercussions of what we do
during the next 24 hours
may be felt for years to come.
I want you to keep a record
of these events
so that history
will have the benefit
of... a dispassionate view.
I will begin immediately, sir.
Is that all?
How is the crew's spirit?
They are
concerned,
of course, Captain,
but confident.
Do you not see that, sir?
Data, unlike King Henry,
it is not easy for me
to disguise myself
and walk among my troops.
That'll be all.
"Now if these men
do not die well
"it will be a black matter
for the king
who led them to it."
Why must we waste time
playing this ridiculous game?
There's more here than
you're telling us.
You're forcing yourself
to hold back.
I have told you
everything relevant
about Nelvana III.
I'm not talking
about the base.
The base is all that matters.
You're lying, Setal.
Go to Nelvana III
and you will see.
We're not going anywhere
until we get to the truth.
You're a spy, aren't you?
No.
Then prove it.
You can begin by telling me
something about the location
and the strength
of the Romulan fleet.
I don't know it.
You're a logistics officer.
For one sector only.
Who was your superior officer?
Admiral Jarok.
The location
of the Romulan bases
along the Neutral Zone?
I don't know.
In your sector?
Irrelevant!
The number of troops
under your admiral's command?
Irrelevant! Irrelevant!
I guess you're right.
It's not worth
playing this game.
Oh, what a fool I've been--
to come looking for courage
in the lair of cowards.
COMPUTER:
Captain Picard, priority message
from Security Officer,
Klingon vessel Bortas.
Mr. Worf, will you handle this
at security station, deck nine?
Aye, sir.
Sensors are configured
for planetary probe, sir.
Ready for launch.
Proceed.
Probe on course.
Sensors are functioning.
Coordinate your analysis
with Mr. La Forge.
I want this report
with dispatch.
I don't know, Data.
My gut tells me
we ought to be listening
to what this guy's
trying to tell us.
Your "gut"?
It's just a...
a feeling, you know--
an instinct, intuition.
But those qualities
would interfere
with rational judgment,
would they not?
You're right,
sometimes they do.
Then why not rely strictly
on the facts?
Because you just can't rely
on the plain and simple facts.
Sometimes they lie.
They can lead
to the wrong conclusions,
but they cannot lie.
Yeah? Well, what
do you think?
Is he a defector or not?
The facts to date would lead
to the objective conclusion
that he is not.
Well... somehow I think
we're going to catch the
Romulans with their pants down
on Nelvana III,
just like he says.
"With their pants...?"
A metaphor.
Catching them in the act.
Because your gut
tells you so.
Exactly.
But you can't always
go with your gut, either.
It's...
Well, it's
a combination, Data.
All right, I'll put it to you
this way.
All these feelings that get
in the way of human judgment,
that confuse the hell out of us,
that make us
second-guess ourselves--
well, we need them.
We need them to...
help us fill in
the missing pieces
because we almost never
have all the facts.
So a person fills in
the missing pieces of the puzzle
with his own personality,
resulting in a conclusion
based as much
on instinct
and intuition
as on fact.
Now you're getting it.
Hmm.
But what does one do
if he has no instinct
or intuition?
Data, look at this.
The facts just took
a left turn.
DATA:
As the probe went into
orbit around Nelvana III,
it began picking up
low-level subspace
radio emissions.
Could they be
naturally occurring?
No, sir, the patterns
are clearly artificial.
The signal was so faint,
our ship's sensors
couldn't read it
from this distance.
Can we decode it?
We've tried.
It's probably Romulan,
but we can't be sure.
We've also picked up
ionization disturbances.
Cloaked Romulan ships
could produce that effect.
What about
the planet's surface?
Reading nothing
but barren rock.
I don't know.
They might be able to hide
a base from our probe.
Its capabilities
are limited.
The only way
we'll know for sure
is if we go down
and take a look
for ourselves.
That'll be all, gentlemen.
I take it, you
have never seen
a Romulan before.
That would be
an incorrect assumption.
Then why do you invade
my privacy?
I was attempting to ascertain
what my guts tell me about you.
You're the android.
I know a host
of Romulan cyberneticists
that would love to be
this close to you.
I do not find that concept
particularly appealing.
Nor should you.
I am told
by various crew members
that this viewport is
their favorite on the ship.
Hmm.
I thought it would bring me
some comfort,
but these are not my stars.
Even the heavens
are denied me here.
Oh... synthetic swill.
I don't suppose
your food terminals
would be capable
of producing a Romulan ale?
I am afraid that would require
the molecular structure
of the beverage in question.
And, as you are no doubt aware
our knowledge of your planet
is quite limited.
The loss is yours.
For I have visited
over a hundred different worlds
and none possessed
the awesome beauty of Romulus.
Am I correct in assuming
you regret your decision
to come here?
What I did had to be done,
but... never again
to see the firefalls
at Gal Gath'thong
and the spires of my home
as they rise
above the Apnex Sea at dawn.
It's a bitter thing
to be exiled from your own home.
It does appear
unlikely
you will ever be allowed
to return to your planet.
The cold reaction
of an android.
But perhaps we can bring Romulus
to you.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
Run program.
After you.
The Valley of Chula.
I know it well.
You are free to stay here
as long as you wish.
I no longer live here.
Turn it off.
Cancel program.
This...
this is my home now,
my future.
I have sacrificed everything.
It must not be in vain.
Arrange a meeting between
myself and Captain Picard.
Tell him Admiral Jarok
wants to see him.
Captain, we have confirmed
that you are holding
Admiral Alidar Jarok.
He has been identified
as the commander
at the massacre
of the Norkan outposts.
The council strongly advises
that you consider Jarok
an unreliable source
of information.
Bring him in.
Ensign, will you
wait outside?
Have a seat,
Admiral Jarok.
Captain, there is
no more time.
Admiral,
have a seat.
You see, I'm just not convinced
that you are telling the truth.
What must I do?
You must convince me.
If I had irrefutable evidence...
but you did not bring
irrefutable evidence.
You brought no evidence at all.
And now I hear you are not
the man you claimed to be.
Admiral...
your credibility
is stretched
beyond belief.
A Romulan defector is almost
a contradiction in terms.
But Admiral Jarok
crossing the lines?
I explained my motivations
to your interrogators.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes--
peace in our galaxy.
Except, Admiral,
you are not a man of peace.
Your military record,
what we know of it, is clear.
Which is precisely why I chose
an alternate identity here.
The massacres in the Norkan
outposts, for example.
What you call "massacres"
were called
the "Norkan campaigns"
on my world, Captain.
One world's butcher
is another world's hero.
Perhaps I am neither one.
On what basis, Admiral,
am I to decide?
Hmm?
Your good word?
Are you willing
to help us overpower
the Romulan B-Type warbirds
we may encounter?
Are you prepared
to help us detect them
through their
cloaking shields?
Well, you see
my problem, Admiral.
You ask us for faith
in circumstances which are
hardly possible to believe
compounded by lies
and your refusal to tell us
what you know.
I cannot betray my people.
You've already betrayed
your people, Admiral.
You've made your choices, sir.
You're a traitor.
Now, if the bitter taste of that
is unpalatable to you,
I am truly sorry.
But I will not
risk my crew
because you think you can dance
on the edge of the Neutral Zone.
You've crossed
over, Admiral.
You make yourself comfortable
with that.
Do you... have any children,
Captain Picard, a family?
No.
Oh. Then you have sacrificed
too much for your career.
Yes, this is all
very interesting...
There comes a time
in a man's life
that you cannot know
when he looks down at the first
smile of his baby girl
and realizes he must change
the world for her--
for all children.
It is for her that I am here.
Not to destroy the Romulan
Empire, but to save it.
For months
I tried desperately
to persuade the High Command
that another war
would destroy the Empire.
They got tired of my arguments.
Finally, I was censured,
sent off to command
some distant sector.
This was my only recourse.
I...
will never see
my child smile again.
She will grow up
believing
that her father is a traitor.
But she will grow up...
if you act, Picard,
if we stop
this war before it begins.
I can't and I won't...
unless I have
unequivocal cooperation.
Admiral Jarok has provided me
with the locations, strengths
and tactical plans
of the Romulan fleet.
Mr. La Forge, he is prepared
to give you data
regarding engines,
weapons, and the
cloaking systems
of the warbird
class starship.
But I believe
his experience as a field
commander will be more valuable
for its strategic sense
than in the technical areas.
Any edge will help, Captain.
Don't depend on this.
For all we know,
he may be still lying,
but we shall find that out
soon enough.
Number One,
set course for Nelvana III.
DATA:
Second Officer's Log,
Stardate 43465.2.
We have entered
the Neutral Zone
in direct violation
of the Treaty of Algeron.
Presuming Romulan warships
are cloaked and monitoring us,
we expect heavy resistance
as we approach Nelvana III.
Tactical?
Nothing on sensors.
I don't like it.
I would have expected
a greeting party.
You echo
another noteworthy commander
in similar circumstances,
Number One.
A countryman
of yours--
George Armstrong Custer
when his Seventh Cavalry
arrived at The Little Bighorn.
May we have better luck.
Approaching Nelvana system.
Engage impulse engines.
Nelvana III on screen.
Still no signs of them
on sensors.
In a way, I'd rather be fighting
my way through this.
It's just too damned easy.
Prepare to enter
standard orbit.
Data?
Scanning
the planet, sir.
No life forms, no power sources,
no weapons systems.
No indication
of a base at all?
DATA:
No, sir.
The subspace signal
the probe detected?
The ionization
disturbances?
DATA:
I am picking them up, sir
but I cannot identify
the source.
They seem to be moving
in an orbital path
with an 800-kilometer apogee.
Lieutenant Worf,
bring the Admiral up here.
Aye, sir.
Maybe they abandoned the planet
after he defected.
There is no scarring
on the planet surface
that would denote heavy
construction of any kind.
A cloaking device of some sort
to hide the entire base?
A cloaking device
operating on the surface
would be given away
by visible distortion effects.
Perhaps you would care
to explain
why we are here, Admiral.
There doesn't appear
to be a base.
I don't understand.
PICARD:
Nelvana III, Admiral!
No base!
No weapons!
No sign of any life at all!
I-I saw
the tactical communiqués--
the records,
timetables for completion.
An entire legion
was assigned to this section.
Is it possible they could have
been feeding you disinformation?
You said
that you had been censured--
reassigned four months ago.
They knew
of your dissatisfaction.
Could all this have been
to test your loyalty?
No.
No!
It's impossible.
They let you escape
with an arsenal
of worthless secrets.
What other explanation
is there?
Permission to withdraw
from the Neutral Zone.
At your earliest convenience,
Number One.
Helm, bring her around
180 degrees!
Geordi,
get us out of here!
GEORDI:
I hear you, Commander.
Two Romulan warships
uncloaking.
Coordinates...
Shields holding.
Damage?
La FORGE:
Minor damage
to the secondary hull.
Power transfer fields
may be pinched off.
I'm working on it.
Captain?
Not yet, Mr. Worf.
This is just a tap
on the shoulder
or we wouldn't be here
talking about it.
The Romulans
are hailing us.
On screen.
TOMALAK:
Captain Picard,
I hardly expected
to see you again so soon.
It seems this time
you are the one
who has made an aggressive move
across the Neutral Zone.
Commander Tomalak,
as I am sure you already know,
we were responding
to warnings
of Romulan incursions
at Nelvana III.
But, Captain, as you can see,
there is no incursion.
And the matter
of the unidentified
subspace radio emissions
and the ionization disturbances?
Oh, you must mean
our orbiting probe.
We are studying Nelvana III
for... archaeological research.
With a cloaked satellite?
Oh, really, Captain,
would you have us believe
this satellite is an excuse
for your aggressive charge
across the Neutral Zone?
You can believe
what you wish,
and we will be on our way.
Without even an apology,
Captain?
If an apology will do,
then I offer it.
I'm afraid it won't,
so I will save you
the humiliation.
Get to it, Tomalak!
You see, Picard,
after we dissect your Enterprise
for every precious bit
of information,
I intend to display
its broken hull
in the center
of the Romulan capitol
as a symbol of our victory.
It will inspire our armies
for generations to come
and serve as a warning
to any other traitor
who would create ripples
of disloyalty.
All the communiqués,
all the timetables,
all the records--
they were all fiction
written
for my benefit.
A test...
a test of my loyalty.
And you used me
to lure the Enterprise
into the
Neutral Zone.
First, Captain, you will
return the traitor, Jarok.
Then you will surrender
as prisoners of war.
Do you seriously expect me
to accept those terms?
No, Captain Picard,
I expect you won't.
You have 30 seconds to decide.
I do not require
one, Tomalak.
I urge you, Captain Picard--
surrender.
Consider the men and women
you would lead
into a lost cause.
If the cause is just
and honorable,
they are prepared
to give their lives.
Are you prepared
to die today, Tomalak?
I expected more from you
than an idle threat, Picard.
Then you shall have it.
Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
Klingon warships--
armed and ready, sir.
What shall it
be, Tomalak?
You will still not survive
our assault.
And you will not survive ours.
Shall we die together?
I look forward to our
next meeting, Captain.
Romulan disrupters
are powering down, sir.
Cancel Red Alert.
Mr. Worf, will
you extend
the appreciation
of the Federation
and my personal gratitude
to the Klingons.
Aye, sir.
Take us back,
Number One.
I did it for nothing.
My home, my family...
for nothing.
He ingested
a Felodesine chip.
He must have
brought it with him.
I'm sorry, Captain,
there was no antidote.
A letter to his wife
and daughter.
Sir, he must have known
it would be impossible
for us to deliver it.
Today, perhaps,
but if there are others
with the courage
of Admiral Jarok,
we may hope to see
a day of peace
when we can
take his letter home.