Captain's Log,
Stardate 43489.2.
We have arrived at Angosia III,
a planet that has expressed
a strong desire
for membership
in the Federation.
Prime Minister Nayrok has
taken Commander Riker and me
on a tour of the capital city.
Well, I'm greatly impressed
with everything I've seen
so far, Prime Minister.
Then, I hope it will
reflect favorably
in your report, Captain.
It's a tribute to your people
that you were able
to recover so rapidly
from the Tarsian War.
It is, indeed.
We are not warriors.
We believe reason
should settle disputes,
but not every culture
agrees with our position.
An unfortunate reality.
The development of the mind
the cultivation
of the intellect--
these are the pursuits
to which the Angosians
have dedicated themselves
for centuries.
Prime Minister?
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but we have a problem.
May I see you
for a moment?
Excuse me,
gentlemen.
Yes, what is it?
Well, I think they'll
make a fine addition
to the Federation,
Number One.
I'm not sure I'd like
to live in this place.
A little stuffy
for my taste.
A prisoner has escaped
from the penal colony
on Lunar V.
Two guards are dead.
The prisoner has taken
a transport vessel.
Do you have means
of pursuit?
The tracking station
was sabotaged.
The entire base is in chaos.
We've ordered ships
from the surface to follow him,
but to be honest,
our civilian pilots
are not trained for this.
With your permission?
Mr. Data,
a stolen transport vessel
has departed from Lunar V.
Have you picked it up
on the sensors?
Yes, Commander.
Good. Detain the vessel
and quarantine the pilot.
Is he armed?
Yes, and extremely dangerous,
Commander.
Lunar V
is a maximum security facility.
Did you read that, Data?
Yes, sir.
We will use extreme caution.
Keep us informed.
Riker out.
On screen, sir.
DATA:
Specifications
on the vessel, Mr. Worf.
No warp drive.
Minimal weaponry.
Heading, Mr. Crusher.
319 mark 250, sir.
Vessel speed increasing
to .02 impulse.
He's seen us, Data.
That's the ship's
drive section.
What happened to the rest
of his ship?
Scan the drive section
for life-form readings.
None.
Bring us around
to the back side
of the asteroid, Mr. Crusher.
Sensors indicate wreckage
on the asteroid surface, Data.
No life signs.
Apparently, he did not survive.
Data, the drive section...
where'd it go?
There's no sign of it
on its previous heading.
Someone must be at the helm.
RIKER:
Status report, Mr. Data.
I am afraid the prisoner
has eluded us, sir.
Eluded the Enterprise?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
We followed procedures
precisely, Captain.
Scanners indicated
no life-forms present
in the drive section.
I cannot explain
how he escaped.
Incoming message from
the Angosian Prime Minister.
On screen.
Captain, we've identified
the prisoner.
His name is Roga Danar.
His criminal record
is too long to go into,
but I must caution you
that he is given to bouts
of uncontrollable violence.
I appreciate your warning,
Prime Minister.
We will keep you informed
of our progress.
Geordi, how far and how fast
can that transport ship travel?
Without warp drive,
there's no way
he could be out
of our range by now.
WESLEY:
We've been sweeping
the area constantly, Commander.
There's nothing
within sensor range.
Cloaking device?
Sir, the Angosians have
no cloaking technology.
Unless he's
borrowing one.
Hmm?
If he's hanging
over the planet's pole,
the magnetic field
would confuse our sensors.
Commander, I believe I can
recalibrate our sensors
to read through
the electromagnetic interference
over the poles.
RIKER:
Let's try it,
Mr. Crusher.
Realign for polar orbit.
Aye, sir.
DATA:
There he is, Commander.
You were correct.
This guy knows all the tricks,
doesn't he?
Still no life-form readings
coming from the vessel.
Could it be
the magnetic interference, Data?
I have compensated.
Still no reading.
We'll have an answer shortly.
Lock on a tractor beam,
Mr. La Forge.
Tractor beam locking on, sir.
He is coming about, sir.
He's out of his mind.
Sensors detect
a massive power buildup
in his aft thrusters.
On main viewer.
He's making a suicide run.
Shields have been
automatically activated.
Tractor beam disengaged.
He bounced off the shields.
That's an interesting twist.
Mr. Crusher, fix coordinates
onto that vessel.
We'll just beam
the whole thing
into a shuttle bay
if we have to.
I do not believe
that will be
necessary, Captain.
He is no longer in
the drive section.
What?
I anticipated
that diversionary tactic
based on his pattern to date.
We are picking up
a cylindrical object
approximately seven meters
in length
and three meters
in diameter.
WORF:
On screen.
PICARD:
Magnify.
An escape pod.
This guy's incredible.
Yet there are still
no life-form readings.
Transporter Room 4,
prepare to beam aboard
from inside that shuttle
anything large enough
to be a humanoid adult.
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir.
Security team, report
to Transporter Room 4.
CREWMAN:
On our way, sir.
We're holding the contents
in stasis
pending the arrival of security.
( beeping )
An illicit weapon
has been detected
in the transporter beam, sir.
It's been rendered inoperable.
Worf, let's greet our guest.
SECURITY CREWMAN:
Bring him in, Mr. O'Brien.
Just stay where you are.
O'BRIEN:
More security,
Transporter Room 4.
More security!
( grunts )
( screams )
( groans )
Oh...
( grunts with effort )
Get him to
a detention cell.
Set phasers
on maximum stun!
( beeping )
O'BRIEN:
Commander...
We'll need a few hours
to get the containment field
on Lunar V operational
before we pick him up.
The damage he did during
his escape was considerable.
We will await
your signal.
I appreciate your patience.
The prison psychologist
recommends
that you keep Danar
fully sedated
until he's ready for transport.
Hmm... Well, he's in our highest
security detention area.
There shouldn't be
any more problems.
Do not relax your security
for an instant, Captain.
He is extremely violent
and very cunning
as you already know.
I will send a transport vessel
to pick him up
as soon as possible.
Nayrok out.
Have you run
a diagnostic
on the
sensors, Data?
Yes, sir. There is nothing wrong
with the ship's sensors.
The reason
we did not pick up life signs
aboard the escape vessel
is because the prisoner
has no life signs.
Computer, identify the occupant
of the detention cell.
COMPUTER:
The detention cell
is vacant at this time.
He's in there.
Could he be some kind
of android?
Our sensors can identify
artificial life-forms, sir.
Apparently, he is capable
of deceiving the sensors.
( startled yell )
( groaning )
( groaning continues )
( moaning )
Are you all right?
What is this ship?
You're onboard
the USS Enterprise.
A war vessel?
A Federation starship.
Federation.
We were
orbiting Angosia
when you escaped
from Lunar V.
Well, it seems that I am
the victim of my own bad timing.
( water splashes )
Are you the keeper of this jail?
I'm Deanna Troi,
Ship's Counselor.
Counselor?
Too bad.
I'd rather you were the jailer
to keep me company
during my return trip.
I assume we
are returning
to Lunar V.
That terrifies you.
I just killed three men
to get out of there, Counselor,
and I'm fully capable
of killing you as well.
That's a terrifying thought,
isn't it?
Even to me.
Do they mistreat you there?
( chuckles ):
Not at all.
I am comfortable,
well fed, and housed.
Oh, no, the Angosians take
good care of their prisoners.
It's simply a matter
of never being able to leave.
What about you, Counselor?
Do you always visit
the prisoners?
Are you a specialist
in criminal behavior?
Or am I just an
interesting specimen
who landed on the ship
like an insect to be studied
under your microscope?
Why do have all this anger
toward me?
A girl with long dark hair
broke my heart a long time ago.
Out of bitterness
and resentment...
I turned to crime.
( laughing )
How about this one--
my mother abandoned me
when I was a little boy.
I never got the guidance
that a wild young man needed.
Why are you doing this?
Playing games?
Isn't that what you do,
Counselor?
Isn't that what all of you
mind-control experts do?
I am not a mind-control expert.
I came here because
I sensed you were in pain.
And what do you sense now?
The pain is gone.
That's interesting, isn't it?
TROI:
There's a duality
about the man.
It's hard
to describe.
He's aware
of his crimes.
In fact,
they trouble him deeply.
Counselor...
He's intelligent, thoughtful,
typically Angosian.
I know what he's done,
but when I'm with him,
I cannot believe
that he is randomly
and deliberately violent.
In fact,
inherently, he has
a nonviolent personality.
Counselor, it took five men
to restrain him
and he took apart half
the transporter room
in the process.
I'm not opening
the door for him, Captain.
I can only tell you
that I sense
something very unusual
about him--
something that is not inherent
to a criminal personality.
In a few hours,
I'll be turning him over
to the Angosians,
and I'll be happy to do it.
I understand.
Data, do we
have a linkup
with the Angosian
central computer?
Yes, Counselor.
We are copying records
for Federation inspection
pursuant to their
application for admittance.
Can I see a police record
on Roga Danar?
DATA:
There is no police record.
That's impossible.
He's been in prison.
Lunar V is
a military prison facility.
Military?
He's a soldier?
That may provide
an explanation
for the tactics
he was able to use against us
when we tried
to capture him.
It doesn't say here
what he was arrested for.
Call up his
military record.
DATA:
He served in many campaigns
during the Tarsian War,
received two promotions
to the rank of "subhadar"--
A very honorable tour of duty.
( sighs )
What was this man's crime?
I've learned
you are
a soldier.
I was a soldier.
Why were you put in prison?
Obviously because
I am a threat to society.
There's no police record.
What did you do?
Everything they asked me to do.
That's why I became
such a threat.
I don't understand.
Why are you bothering to try,
Counselor?
Because I want to help if I can.
Unlock the door.
You are a nonviolent man,
yet you committed acts
of excessive violence.
You can learn to do it
if you have to.
Did you have to?
It was war.
So it started with the war.
It started the day
I volunteered, Counselor,
the day I began training,
the day I met
my first instructor,
and he also called himself
a "Counselor."
Roga Danar was
an idealistic young man
who answered his people's call
to service.
He joined the military
to help fight
for the Angosian way of life.
What he didn't realize
was that, by doing so,
he would have to give up
that way of life forever.
He's not the same man
who left home to go to war.
He's been through intense
psychological manipulation
and biochemical
modifications.
At Troi's request,
I examined him.
His cell structure
has been significantly altered.
They used a combination
of cryptobiolin,
triclenidil, macrospentol,
and a few things
I can't even recognize.
Was he a prisoner of war?
Who did this to him?
His own government.
He's been programmed
to be the perfect soldier.
He can be absolutely normal,
but when a danger is perceived,
the programming clicks in
and takes over.
Memory, strength, intelligence,
reflexes-- all become enhanced.
He's conditioned
to survive at any cost.
One of the new substances
in his cellular structure
even shields
electrical impulses.
Perhaps that would explain why
our sensors did not detect him.
Why was he assigned
to the Lunar V facility?
He committed no crime.
He says he was ordered there
with others like him.
When the first soldiers
returned to Angosia,
they had trouble.
The rules changed too quickly.
A lost temper
could result in murder.
DATA:
Counselor,
did no one attempt
to adjust their programming?
They were just exiled
to Lunar V.
Lunar V...
an orbiting gulag.
What do you want?
Am I disturbing you?
Yes!
Then I will leave.
No, wait, wait.
I'd rather talk
to someone.
Why do you have yellow eyes?
I am an android.
I believe you and I have
something in common.
We do?
Yes. We have both
been programmed.
Ah, yes, yes, you've been
talking to Counselor Troi.
It is not at all
the same, android.
I do not mean to belittle
your condition.
I understand your dilemma,
but I am curious.
My program can be altered.
Yours cannot?
The man I was is still
inside me,
but this... this conditioning
has been imposed--
woven together with my thoughts
and my feelings
and my responses.
How do you separate
the program from the man?
Without further analysis
of your condition
from Counselor Troi
or Dr. Crusher,
I cannot say,
but I believe
it is possible.
Yeah, doctors.
The Angosian doctors
did this to me.
If it could be undone,
wouldn't they undo it?
I cannot answer that.
Nor can I.
Yet I ask myself that question
every moment of every day.
Captain, what this man
has been telling you
is full of half-truths.
He's a prisoner.
What do you expect him
to say about us?
Well, perhaps you would
clarify it for me.
The soldiers were resettled
on Lunar V.
It was to be their colony.
Was it a resettlement
of their choosing?
It was for their own protection,
as well as that of others.
Most of them
are quite happy there.
We went to great lengths to give
them a fine quality of life.
Prime Minister,
even the most comfortable prison
is still a prison.
Unfortunately,
a few agitators like Danar
forced us to add security.
My medical team suggests
that there may be
alternative treatment.
Captain, I assure you
that every alternative
has been explored,
and this discussion
is now treading upon matters
of internal security.
This is not your concern.
I have dispatched a ship
to rendezvous with you
to transport the prisoner
back to Lunar V.
On behalf of Angosia,
I thank the Federation
for its assistance
in retrieving our citizen.
"Matter of internal security"--
the age-old cry
of the oppressor.
Were you built for combat,
android?
No, but my program does include
military strategy.
That is how I was able
to anticipate your final tactic
and capture you.
You did that?
Perhaps you would be
better at combat than you think.
Except that I am
not programmed to kill.
My improved reflexes have
allowed me to kill 84 times,
and my improved memory
lets me remember
each of those 84 faces.
Can you understand
how that feels?
I am incapable of any feeling.
Why, then, I envy you.
( door opening )
Roga, this is
Captain Picard.
Captain.
Mr. Danar,
I am transferring you
to Angosian security.
They're en route.
They will arrive shortly.
I wanted to tell you
I have no choice.
The Prime Minister insisted,
and we have no right to refuse.
Well, you would be foolish
to consider it otherwise,
Captain,
for they are very correct.
I am dangerous.
There is no place for me
in a civilized society.
I do not believe that.
Nor do I.
I respect my officers'
judgments.
I wish I could help further.
If a way appears, I will.
I appreciate you telling me
that face to face.
I thought you deserved
that much.
And you deserve
to know
that I must use
whatever means I can to escape.
WORF:
Captain, the Angosian
transport vessel has arrived.
Inform them the transport
will take place shortly.
Picard out.
Mr. Data, to the Bridge, please.
Take care of
yourself, android.
I enjoyed our talk.
I, too.
Perhaps when this planet
becomes a member of the
Federation, we'll be able...
I will not
be there
to see it, Counselor
because even with this
overwhelming demand to survive
that they have built
into my soul,
I would rather die
than return to Lunar V.
Captain Picard, we're ready
to receive the prisoner.
Now transmitting the coordinates
of our holding cell.
( beeping )
Coordinates received, sir.
Stand by
for transport.
Picard out.
Mr. Worf, have all security
precautions been taken?
Release of the force field
and activation
of the transporter
will be virtually simultaneous.
There will only be a .1 second
difference between them.
Even Danar can't
move that fast.
There will be
a full security contingent
present.
Proceed.
Transporter Room One
to Lieutenant Worf.
We're ready, sir.
Energizing.
WORF:
O'Brien, increase
transporter power.
I'm losing him.
TROI:
Roga, don't!
You'll be killed!
( explosion )
What the hell...?
( alarm beeping )
Security personnel--
full alert.
Shut down all
shuttle bays,
transporters,
and turbolifts.
WORF:
Captain, a phaser is missing.
We must assume that he is armed.
Sound general quarters.
Clear all corridors
of nonessential personnel.
We don't want him
taking any hostages.
General quarters sounded, sir.
Raise security containment
fields immediately
on decks 34, 35, and 36.
Aye, sir.
Data, put
the turbolifts
back on line.
If Danar sees
they're operating,
he may try to use them.
As soon as he does,
we have him.
Sir, unauthorized access
of turbolift five on deck 34.
He took the bait.
Data, override its
destination.
Divert that turbolift
to a position near
to Lieutenant Worf's
present location.
Four seconds to arrival, sir.
We're in position.
( electronic shrieking )
Phaser on overload!
Seal this deck!
( shrieking intensifies )
( shrieking stops )
WORF:
Captain, the overload
has been averted.
( grunts and yells )
( beeps )
Drop force field on deck 36.
Sir, containment field down
on deck 36.
How the hell did
he manage that?
He's headed for Engineering.
Riker to La Forge.
Engineering, respond.
Engineering?
Engineering, come in.
Geordi, are you okay?
Captain, someone
in Engineering
is attempting to override
the security system lockout.
Riker to Worf.
He's in Engineering.
Acknowledged, Commander.
We're on our way.
Data, I want you
to stall Danar.
Allow him to think
he's succeeding.
As he bypasses each subsystem,
I can reroute it
without his knowledge.
Make it so.
Danar is extremely adept, sir.
I am not certain
which security measure
he is attempting to circumvent.
Sir, Danar
has succeeded
in restoring power
to Shuttle Bay 2.
I have overridden
Danar's bypass.
Shuttle Bay 2 is
once again inactive.
Very good, Mr. Data.
Now I know
where he's headed.
You okay?
Geordi!
I'm all right.
He took us by surprise.
He came out of nowhere.
I didn't think anyone
could move that fast.
DATA:
Lieutenant, I am reading
an open panel--
K-12, J-9, deck 30.
Acknowledged.
Danar must have climbed
up the reactor core
and gotten into
a Jefferies tube.
He could be anywhere.
We believe he is attempting
to reach Shuttle Bay 2.
That's 25 decks
up from here--
quite a climb,
but I wouldn't
put it past him.
There is a full contingent
of security at all Shuttle Bays.
You want my advice?
Double it!
( beeping )
Captain, reading another
open access panel.
Security team
to Jefferies tube J-4, deck 15.
Security, acknowledged.
Deck 15-- a few decks
below the Shuttle Bay.
Sir, I find it highly unlikely
that Danar would be attempting
to reach Shuttle Bay 2.
Explain.
In our previous
encounter,
Danar employed a strategy
of misdirection
in an attempt
to gain his objective.
And you believe he's using
the same tactic now?
He is aware that our sensors
are unable to track him,
yet he seems to be purposely
leaving a trail
for us to follow.
Where do you think
he's headed?
I am afraid his true destination
remains a mystery.
Readings now indicate
an open access panel
in Jefferies tube
N-11, deck 38.
He's doubled back on us.
The cargo bays.
Advise all personnel on deck 38
to stay out of the cargo bays.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Status, Mr. Data?
They appear to be empty, sir.
Good. I want you to flood them
with anesthizine.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
( loud hissing )
( equipment powering up )
Sensors show anesthizine
concentration
70 parts per million
within the
cargo bays.
That should put our boy
to sleep.
Return environmental conditions
to normal, Mr. Data.
Move in your security teams,
Mr. Worf.
Acknowledged.
Worf to Bridge.
We have found no sign
of the intruder,
but there is
a missing pressure suit
from Cargo Bay 3.
Pressure suit?
RIKER:
Could be he's planning
to enter Shuttle Bay 2
from outside the Enterprise,
bypassing
the security guards.
Mr. Worf, post security guards
at all emergency airlocks
on decks 37 through 39.
Aye, sir.
I'll also cover
the photon torpedo launchers.
Danar may attempt
to leave the ship that way.
Worf out.
WORF:
Danar!
You are cunning.
You must have Klingon blood,
but the battle is over.
My battle is never over.
Worf to Bridge--
I have Danar.
Explosion in Jefferies tube,
section T-95.
All external sensors
inoperative.
Go to backup systems.
Unable to transfer control, sir.
( both grunting and groaning )
( beeping )
Sit down, gentlemen.
( groaning )
( equipment powering down )
Worf to Bridge.
RIKER:
Go ahead.
Danar has escaped.
He used a phaser
to power the cargo transporter.
Coordinates indicate
he beamed aboard
the Angosian transport ship.
Data, can you verify that?
Negative, sir. All
external sensors
still nonfunctioning.
Then we have no way
to track him.
That was his plan all along.
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
We are continuing to repair
damage to the ship's sensors
following the escape of
the Angosian prisoner Danar.
He is still at large.
Engineering, I'm getting
readings on tactical.
Are we back up?
LA FORGE:
That's affirmative, Commander.
Mr. Worf, sweep the area.
Captain, the Prime Minister
is hailing us, priority one.
On screen.
WORF:
Priority channel cleared.
Yes, Prime Minister?
Captain, I've just been informed
that Roga Danar has attacked
the penal colony on Lunar V.
Attacked it?
In our own police shuttle.
Several of my people
have been wounded.
Hundreds of prisoners
are rioting.
Some of them have escaped
with Danar
and, at last report, are headed
toward the capital city.
Captain, we are not suited
to handle situations like this.
That's what we created them for.
We'll send an away team,
Prime Minister.
Picard out.
Counselor Troi,
Commander Data, Mr. Worf--
you will accompany me
to the planet.
And my understanding is
that these men
are programmed to survive.
Is that correct?
Yes, Captain.
And that they
will not kill
unless their survival
is at stake.
It is against their
nature to do so, Captain.
Then let us hope they
do not believe their
survival is at stake.
Mr. Worf...
You are personally responsible
for the Captain's safety.
I understand,
Commander.
( talking quietly )
I don't expect them
to listen to reason.
I loathe the idea
of a violent confrontation,
but we must
be prepared.
( whoosh of beam down )
MAN:
Is that it?
MAN 2:
I don't know.
This is all you've brought?
Where are
your security men?
We're not here
to fight your wars for you.
They have been seen
moving towards
the center of the city.
People are scared.
Don't you understand, Captain?
They're dangerous.
You are dangerous.
They're only victims.
You made them what they are.
You asked them
to defend your way of life
and then you discarded them.
They were not happy here.
They were not welcome here.
It was the will of the people
to resettle them.
No one was pleased
with the solution,
but we had to act
for the greater good.
DATA:
Prime Minister,
if you have the skills to
create a master soldier,
can you not counteract
the effect?
The chemicals can be removed
from their systems,
but we're not convinced
that the psychological
conditioning
can ever be entirely reversed.
Have you tried, sir?
We studied it thoroughly.
Even before the training began,
we knew there would be
problems reversing it.
It was a risk we had to take.
Did you reveal that risk
to the men who volunteered
for service?
We were helping them
to survive the war.
You understand?
They needed
those skills.
They're your brothers,
your sons,
and you turned your backs
on them.
TROI:
There are methods
of treatment.
Until you try them,
how can you know
they won't work?
Even a partial recovery
could give them some peace.
It was the will of the people.
To allow them to suffer?
PRIME MINISTER:
There was a referendum.
The people weighed
the costs involved.
They chose
the settlement solution.
Besides, we may need
to use them again someday.
Have you understood one
word that we have said?
ANGOSIAN:
Move in.
Freeze!
Nobody move!
No, Worf!
All of you--
don't respond.
Don't provoke them further.
Keep those weapons down
unless you wish
to be killed.
Do as he says.
No!
Don't.
Shoot us.
Destroy us.
Do what you have to,
but you will not ignore us.
Come on, do it!
You cowards.
Yes, and you're not programmed
to murder cowards.
So if they will not fight back,
what will you do?
We will not go back.
You were programmed
to survive.
You can survive at
the Lunar V settlement.
To survive is not enough.
To simply exist is not enough.
Roga, tell them what you want.
We want our lives back.
We want to come home.
I am not prepared
to negotiate
under threat, Danar.
But if you will
put down your weapons
and return peaceably
to Lunar V...
I would be willing.
Mr. Prime Minister,
with all due respect,
you will have to force us
or at least try.
Captain, you must
do something.
Call your ship.
Quite right,
Prime Minister.
Enterprise, prepare to beam
the away team back.
RIKER:
At your command, Captain.
Picard, you can't
leave us
like this.
I have all the information
I need for my report.
Your prisoner has
been returned to you
and you have
a decision to make--
whether to try
and force them back
or welcome
them home.
In your
own words--
this is not
our affair.
We cannot
interfere
in the natural course of
your society's development,
and I'd say it's going
to develop significantly
in the next few minutes.
It's been an interesting visit.
When you're ready
for membership,
the Federation will be pleased
to reconsider your application.
Mr. Riker,
four to beam up.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
Success, Captain?
Number One,
will you note in our report
that if the government
of Angosia survives the night,
we will offer them
Federation assistance
in their efforts
to reprogram their veterans.
And if the government
doesn't survive?
I have a feeling
they will choose to.
Mr. Crusher,
set coordinates
for Starbase
Lyra III.
Coordinates set, sir.
Engage.