Captain's Log,
Stardate 43510.7:
The Enterprise
has put in at Rutia IV
to deliver medical supplies
following an outbreak
of violent protests.
Although non-aligned,
the planet has enjoyed
a long trading relationship
with the Federation.
Now, a generation of peace
has ended
with terrorist attacks
by Ansata separatists
who are demanding autonomy
and self-determination
for their homeland
on the western continent.
Recreational shore leave
has been prohibited
and all away teams have been
instructed to beam down armed.
We have only a few minutes
before our next meeting, Doctor.
It's all right,
we're finished.
Waiter.
( explosion )
( people screaming )
( alarm blaring )
Doctor!
SECURITY:
Keep back.
CRUSHER:
Put that away.
I'm a doctor.
Just lie still.
Try not to move.
Lieutenant Worf, I need
some bandages, disinfectant--
something with
alcohol in it.
Doctor, it is not safe.
That's an order, Lieutenant.
( alarm stops )
SECURITY:
You there,
clear this area.
Don't be afraid.
There's a lot of bleeding,
but it's not as bad as it looks.
The Klingon's right.
These Ansata,
they're madmen.
There could be
another bomb.
( coughs )
Clear this area.
Everyone out...
Doctor, I believe
it would be prudent
to return
to the Enterprise.
There are physicians
on this planet.
Who are not here.
I am.
SECURITY:
Everyone out.
This way.
Doctor.
Thank you.
Not at all, Doctor.
Captain,
there has been an incident.
A bomb has been detonated
by Ansata terrorists.
Your security status?
Vulnerable, sir.
Transporter Room 3,
lock onto the away team.
Prepare to beam them back.
CREWMAN: Yes, Captain.
Sir, I've recommended
such a course,
but there are several wounded
and Dr. Crusher
is insisting on attending to...
I understand.
Picard to Dr. Crusher.
Go ahead.
Doctor, Commander Data has
informed me of your situation.
I already know
what you're going to say.
Doctor, will you
at least allow...
The longer we argue, the longer
it's going to take me to save...
Doctor, you are endangering
yourself and the away team.
Captain, I am trying to put life
back into a wounded body
with sleight of hand,
I'm not going anywhere.
Data and Worf
don't have to stay.
Crusher out.
Transporter Room, do you have
a lock on the away team?
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir. Shall
I transport them?
I don't want to be in the
transporter room to greet her.
Commander Data,
hold your position until the
Rutian medics arrive.
Aye, sir.
The tricorder is not reading
any other explosive devices
in this vicinity.
SECURITY:
Get out of the way!
Move!
What...
( yells )
You don't understand,
I'm a...
PICARD:
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
A transporter would leave
residual ionization in the air.
Our tricorder readings found
no trace after the incident.
People don't just appear
and disappear.
There must be some way
to track her.
We have been unable to detect
a signal from her communicator.
Either it has been deactivated
or she is being held
in a shielded location.
Why her?
WORF:
Sir, I believe
she was the intended target
of the abduction.
Why would they want to take
a Federation hostage?
Their fight doesn't involve us.
It does now.
You hungry?
You want something to eat?
Doesn't matter to me.
You want to be hungry,
be hungry.
What's your name?
You're a doctor
on a Federation starship.
I always wondered
what it would be like
to travel across the galaxy.
It's not something
I've exactly had time for.
This isn't the best way
to meet new people, is it?
If you need anything,
ask for me.
My name is Kyril Finn.
They know me.
We have no reason to believe
she's been hurt in any way.
In fact, it's more than likely
they will take good care of her
if they want to use her
as a bargaining chip.
Bargaining chip?
The innocent often
become pawns
in conflicts of
this type, Wes.
You see, the Ansata
separatists
have been trying for generations
to free themselves
from the rule
of the eastern continent.
And if they can get
the government
just to acknowledges
their demands,
then kidnapping your mother
will have served its purpose.
I think, that's
what they may be after,
but it may not.
Frankly, Wesley,
I don't care.
My only concern
is to get your mother back.
And very shortly,
we shall be leaving
to have a meeting
with the authorities.
Request permission to be
on the away team, sir.
No. You have an important job
to do here.
If we are to free your mother,
then we have to be able to trace
the movements of the terrorists.
I want you to work with
the team that are investigating
this new technology of theirs.
( sighs )
I understand.
Report to Mr. Data.
Dismissed.
He needs your
strength right now.
History has shown us
that strength may be useless
when faced with terrorism.
And what exactly
is Ansata policy
with regard to hostages?
I doubt if they have one.
They don't usually
take hostages.
These are not people
we're dealing with here.
They're animals.
Fanatics who kill
without remorse or conscience,
who think nothing
of murdering innocent people.
But they could just as easily
have shot her where she stood.
Don't ask me
to explain them.
I can't.
The atrocities
that I've seen...
And now they have
this new device
that makes them
even more deadly.
How do I combat an enemy
that fails to register
on any scanner
until they're literally
standing in front of you
pointing a phaser
at your head?
What can you tell us
about this device?
Not much really.
They first started
using it two months ago.
We've taken several of these
off dead terrorists.
Our people have
looked at them.
Nothing they
can explain.
Do you mind if we take
one of these with us
and have our people
study it?
Not at all.
And I'll put you in touch with
our research people if you wish.
I appreciate your help.
Perhaps if we found
ourselves in possession
of some of that advanced
Federation weaponry of yours,
it would shift the balance
of power back to our favor.
Of course, you know
that is out of the question.
Yes, of course.
I would like to leave
Commander Riker here
to assist in your search
for Dr. Crusher.
If you like.
You don't sound
very optimistic.
I know my enemy, Commander.
They don't leave much room
for optimism.
You hungry?
You want something to eat?
Relax, relax.
I'm just going to...
Now, eat something.
What's the point
of not eating?
You're the only one
who suffers.
Do I look like
it's bothering me?
Okay, it's bothering me.
Come on.
No forks, sorry.
Did I mention my name is Finn?
And you're...
Why have you brought me here?
I need a doctor.
There are doctors on Rutia.
I need somebody better.
I heard you were
with the Federation flagship
and I knew you had to be.
Who told you that?
I heard.
Now you'll help me
just like you helped them.
What are you talking about?
Your ship carries
medical supplies for them--
for the other side.
Why does the Federation
ally itself with the Rutians?
We don't.
All we did was bring--
Medical supplies.
People were hurt.
I know.
I hurt them.
You're finished eating.
Get up.
I have a son.
You'll be with him
again, Doctor.
I see no reason to kill you.
( moaning )
I need some instruments
from my ship
in order to diagnose this.
And you think if I allow
you to contact your ship
they will transport
the instruments?
When I inform the Captain
how serious the situation is,
I'm sure he'll agree.
I've told you, Finn,
the Federation is not allied
with the Rutians.
We're here
on an errand of mercy.
And since the Federation
does not wish to take sides,
they will send
the supplies that you need.
Absolutely.
I've anticipated
your needs.
These are Federation supplies.
The ones we had delivered
to the medical dispensary.
I heard.
You mean to tell me all these
people belong to the Ansata?
No, not really.
We suspect
the organization itself
only to consist
of some 200 members.
There are over 5,000
names on this list.
Citizens we know to be
sympathetic to their cause.
They pass along weaponry
and information
march in pro-Ansata
demonstrations
participate in
general strikes
or the occasional riot.
How did this ever
get started?
70 years ago,
we denied them independence.
That gave them
a noble cause.
Now it's just an excuse
for more violence.
You hate them as much
as they hate you.
Believe it or not,
I always considered
myself moderate.
What changed your mind?
Being stationed here
for six months
watching the body count grow.
The three assassination
attempts on my life.
Well, that'll change
your point of view.
The event that really
opened my eyes
took place only a few
days after my arrival.
A terrorist bomb
destroyed a shuttlebus.
60 schoolchildren.
There were no survivors.
The Ansata claimed
that it was a mistake--
that their intended target
was a police transport.
As if that made
everything all right.
That day, I vowed
that I would put an end
to terrorism in this city...
and I will.
Thank you.
You're very helpful.
You could learn to do this
when you grow up.
If you grow up.
They're dying.
I'm seeing a complicated
set of conditions.
Their DNA is warped somehow
and it's distorting their
entire cellular chemistry.
You can't do anything?
I can make them more
comfortable, that's all.
The damage is too extensive.
( inaudible )
If I could detect their
condition earlier...
You could reverse
the damage?
Perhaps.
I don't know.
What happened
to them?
It's the inverter.
It's given our cause a new life
but... it asks
for our lives in return.
What does it do?
We transport through
a dimensional shift
that the Rutian
sensors can't trace.
Dimensional shifting?
You can't do that
with humanoid tissue.
There are risks,
the designers told us,
but... it works.
You're showing the same
distorted readings.
Not as severe
as the others, but...
Doesn't matter.
It does if it kills you.
Don't you know?
A dead martyr is worth
10 posturing leaders.
A subspace field coil with
an isolated power source.
Curious.
Hey, guys,
come here.
Look at this.
The Rutian team picked up
a faint nuclear vibration
during the terrorist movements.
Nuclear vibration?
That could
possibly indicate
subspace transition rebound
during transport.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
May I?
Mm-hmm.
Computer, call up
the files on...
Oh, what was his name?
We spent two hours on him
in astral physics last year.
Uh... folded-space transport.
Adaptive transport?
Yes.
Are you referring
to the Elway theorem?
Yes. Computer, call up
the files on the Elway theorem.
What if they're using
inter-dimensional travel?
But the Elway theorem proved
to be entirely inaccurate.
All research was abandoned
by the mid-23rd century.
But, Data, look-- the nuclear
vibrations are the same
and Elway used a model
similar to this.
It would certainly
be untraceable
by any standard method
of detection.
But it was proven
to be fatal.
To use this technology
would be an irrational act.
We may be dealing with
irrational people, Data.
Is there a way
to trace this?
With an adaptive
subspace echogram, maybe.
Captain, anyone who is willing
to transport in this manner
would suffer significant
internal damage
that could be detected.
Hmm. It sounds as though
they may require
the services...
of a doctor.
( buzz of conversation )
Excuse me.
( indistinct
radio transmission )
This is no way to live.
For us or them?
For both of you.
I know it's
not pretty, Riker,
but this is what terrorism
has done to this city.
There's got to be a better way
to deal with it than this.
My methods may seem harsh
but, believe me,
they're gentle compared
to my predecessors.
Suspects would be brought
into police headquarters
and mysteriously vanish.
I put a stop to that.
What happened
to your predecessors?
They were murdered.
Are you going to tell me that
little boy's a threat?
It's possible.
That shuttlebus
I told you about?
The bomb was set
by a teenager.
In a world where children
blow up children,
everyone's a threat.
It's okay.
Over there.
You should be drawing,
not killing people.
I can do both.
How can you have such a casual
attitude toward killing?
I take my killing
very seriously, Doctor.
You are an idealist.
I live in an ideal culture.
There's no need for
your kind of violence.
We've proven that.
Your origins on Earth
are from the American
continent, are they not?
North America.
Yes, I've read
your history books.
This is a war
for independence
and I am no different than your
own George Washington.
Washington was a military
general, not a terrorist.
The difference between
generals and terrorists, Doctor,
is only the difference
between winners and losers.
You win, you're called
a general, you lose...
You are killing
innocent people.
Can't you see the immorality
of what you're doing?
Or have you killed so much
you've become blind to it?
How much innocent blood
has been spilled
for the cause of freedom
in the history
of your Federation, Doctor?
How many good
and noble societies
have bombed civilians in war,
have wiped out whole cities?
And now that you enjoy
the comfort that has come
from their battles,
their killing,
you frown on
my immorality?
I am willing to die
for my freedom, Doctor.
And in the finest tradition
of your own great civilization,
I'm willing to
kill for it, too.
All right,
you can go.
SECURITY:
Next man.
If you want, I could
become more persuasive.
No.
You're Katik Shaw,
the waiter from the Lumar Cafe.
You witnessed both the explosion
and the kidnapping.
I saw nothing.
We're aware of your ties
with the Ansata.
For all we know,
you planted the bomb yourself.
Where have they
taken her?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I've had enough of this.
I want you to take a message
back to your people.
You tell them the Federation
is willing to negotiate
for the release of
Dr. Crusher.
Riker!
She's a Starfleet officer
and she's my responsibility.
If your people have terms,
we're willing to listen.
We want her back.
It's as simple as that.
I don't think it's necessary
to detain this gentleman
any longer.
Get out.
I should have
him followed,
but we'll try it your way.
Is that what you want?
What I want...
is to go home.
Back to my own country.
To leave behind the roundups,
the interrogations,
the bodies
lying in the street.
To be able to walk
without the bodyguards.
And not to have to jump
at every unexpected noise.
That's what I want, Riker.
A dimensional jump
can create
subspace pressure
modulation, Captain.
By setting up
a magnetosphere echogram
that can monitor each
of their movements,
we may be able to
collect enough data
to trace their
power source.
Can you estimate the number
of jumps it would take?
Dimensional shifting is such
an unstable procedure, sir,
that I cannot say.
Sir, I am finding it
difficult
to understand many aspects
of Ansata conduct.
Much of their behavioral norm
would be defined by my program
as unnecessary
and unacceptable.
Mm-hmm. By my "program,"
as well, Data.
But if that
is so, Captain,
why are their methods
so often successful?
I have been reviewing the
history of armed rebellion.
And it appears
that terrorism
is an effective way to
promote political change.
Yes, it can be, but I have
never subscribed to the theory
that political power flows
from the barrel of a gun.
Yet, there are
numerous examples
when it was successful.
The independence of the
Mexican State from Spain,
the Irish Unification
of 2024,
and the Kenzie Rebellion.
Yes, I'm aware of them.
Then would it be
accurate to say
that terrorism is acceptable
when all options
for peaceful settlement
have been foreclosed?
( sighs )
Data, these are questions
that mankind
has been struggling with
throughout history.
Your confusion is...
only human.
Finn, everyone
is being rounded up.
Because of her?
The Federation wants
to negotiate a release.
While they arrange
for the Rutian police
to fill up
the detention cells.
A Starfleet officer
is working with the director.
He wants a meeting with you.
Oh, I'm sure he does.
Your Federation colleagues
have engineered mass arrests
to pressure me
into releasing you.
I'm sure you've
misunderstood.
They're working with the police.
He's seen it with his own eyes.
All they want
is to get me back safely.
I'm not releasing you.
I need you here.
To find a way to
reverse the effects
of the dimensional shift?
I can do that right now.
Stop using it.
I have a life, Finn.
I have a son who needs me.
Is your son
on the ship?
Yes.
( sighs )
I'm sorry
he's on the ship.
No.
They have joined forces
with the Rutians against us.
We are not your enemy.
They are more valuable
to me than an enemy.
For 70 years, we have shouted
and no one has heard us.
Destroy the Federation flagship,
someone will listen.
Please...
They are the ones
who interfered.
They are the ones who
sent medical supplies.
organized mass arrests.
They are killing
your son, not me.
Please, Finn, don't do this.
I will do anything you ask.
I had a son, too.
He was 13 when he died
in detention.
( indistinct conversation )
What?
( screams )
( console beeps )
Intruder alert, deck 12.
Another subspace reflection.
Dimensional shift, sir.
Go to Red Alert.
Sound general quarters.
( alarm blaring )
( yelling )
Security to Engineering!
Intruders in Engineering.
Casualties reported
on deck 12.
Sick Bay responding.
Seal off all decks.
Lock on transporters
to intruder signals.
CREWMAN:
Intruder signals unstable,
Captain.
I cannot lock on.
They are moving
interdimensionally.
Neither transporters nor force
fields will contain them, sir.
( ticking )
Explosive charge
on the main warp chamber.
Transporter Room 3,
lock on to the explosive device
and energize.
CREWMAN:
It's scrambling
the sensors, Captain.
I can't pinpoint it.
Begin emergency evacuation.
Stand by for saucer separation.
Mr. La Forge, can you remove
the charge from the engine core?
I'm trying. Hold on.
They've got it
locked on somehow.
Stand by.
Transporter Room,
lock on my signal
and stand by to transport
two kilometers
off the starboard nacelle.
His signal?
Transporter Room-- now!
Mr. La Forge, report.
Transport complete, Captain.
I have a man down.
More dimensional shifts, sir.
PICARD:
Can you calibrate
their destination?
No, sir, the readings are...
( groans )
Security,
Code 1 Emergency!
Security!
Lieutenant Worf is
recovering in Sick Bay.
The wound was
not severe.
Dead? Injured?
Three dead, four wounded.
Another millisecond
and there would have been
a big dust cloud orbiting Rutia
instead of the Enterprise.
Why?
I just asked
if they would talk.
You have
your answer, Riker.
WESLEY:
Sir.
The next time the Ansata
use their dimensional jump,
we should be able to get a fix
on the power source.
Worf went down.
I don't know if
he's alive or dead.
And there were
other casualties.
Was Wes on the Bridge?
Yes.
He took cover.
I didn't see
any more than that.
But you are
all right, though?
Yes, they needed
a doctor.
Uh-huh. The side effects
of the transport.
Yes.
We're getting closer to
tracing their movements.
Actually, it was
Wesley who put us
onto this dimensional
jump of theirs.
He has been
extraordinary, Beverly.
He's going to make
a very fine officer.
He's had good role models.
I'm sorry. If I'd only gone
back to the ship...
I should have
beamed you up.
You wouldn't dare.
Oh, yes, I would...
and should.
Without my permission?
If you don't
follow orders...
If you'd give reasonable
orders, I'd obey.
Doctor, I will be the judge
of what is reasonable.
There aren't any exits
to the surface.
So the only way out
is by the transporter
or the dimensional jump.
A mode of travel
I'd encourage you to avoid.
It's killing them.
They're mad.
I don't know anymore.
The difference
between a madman
and a committed man
willing to die for a cause...
it's all become blurred
over the last few days.
Beverly, I don't
have to remind you
of the psychological impact
of being a hostage.
I know.
I understand that.
But their leader, Finn,
he's not what you'd expect.
No, he's certainly not
what I would expect.
Without cause or reason,
he and his little band of
outlaws have attacked my ship.
But he did have reasons.
The medical supplies,
the arrests...
Jean-Luc, if we really examined
our role in all this...
Beverly, you are
arguing for a man
who may have
murdered your son.
I didn't kill
your son, Beverly.
We weren't able
to destroy the ship.
We had to settle for him.
She wouldn't even
tell me her name.
I call her Doctor.
You have made a grave
miscalculation.
Oh?
You've assaulted
a Federation starship,
killed and wounded several
members of her crew,
kidnapped two
of her officers,
and you don't
expect a response?
On the contrary,
I'm counting on it.
You want Federation
involvement?
Captain,
the Federation has
a lot to admire in it,
but there's a hint
of moral cowardice
in your dealings
with non-aligned planets.
You're doing business with a
government that is crushing us.
And you say
you're not involved.
You're very,
very much involved.
You just don't want
to get dirty.
You accuse us
of cowardice
while you plant
bombs in shadows?
I am fighting
the only war that I can
against an intractable enemy.
Now, I'm fighting a big war
against a more
powerful adversary.
Can't you see
how that helps me?
I'm afraid I can't.
He's added another chair
to the negotiating table.
You added the chair, Captain.
I am simply forcing you
to sit in it.
The Federation will quickly tire
of our little war.
They'll want you back.
They will want to get
as far from Rutia as they can
and I will not make it easy.
Eventually, the Federation
will force the government
into making concessions,
and then a few more,
and then... a few more.
Until we can finally reach
an honorable agreement
that saves face
for all sides--
except... we win.
You understand, I will not
cooperate with you in any way.
You've already cooperated,
Captain...
just by coming here.
( gasps )
I am not here to hurt you.
Just hear what I have to say.
Your people are safe.
How long they stay that way
depends on you.
We demand an embargo
and trade sanctions
levied against Rutia.
The Federation
will blockade the planet.
No ships will be
allowed in or out.
This will continue
until the government of Rutia
consents to talks mediated
by a Federation counsel.
You have 12 hours
to make your decision.
( console beeping )
Got it.
We've pinpointed
the Ansata base
as some 300 kilometers
from the city
on the southern tip
of the continent.
Sensors indicate
it is located
30 meters below the ground,
implying a cavern-like dwelling.
Any passages leading
to the surface?
Our readings show no evidence
of any, Commander.
Any light they have must be
artificially generated.
If we could
shut that down,
you could use the confusion
to find your people.
Request permission to join
the rescue party, sir.
I owe it to the Captain.
Permission granted.
You have the Bridge,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
Commander?
Good luck.
We'll bring
them home, Wes.
You're glad to see
your Captain.
Yes.
I may have to kill him.
I just wanted
to warn you.
He can help you, Finn.
He is very influential...
He will not help us.
If you could just
convince him that your...
You may be able to
convince him, perhaps, not I.
I've talked to him.
I'll try.
If our places were reversed,
I would expect to die.
Your places would
never be reversed.
He would never
forcibly abduct you
or play games
with your life.
He would treat you
with respect.
I've treated you with respect.
You've scared
the hell out of me, Finn!
You've controlled me
through fear
just like you've tried
to control this whole continent.
You haven't tasted
real fear yet, Doctor.
Is that the best you can do?
Is fear the only weapon
you have?
No, but...
it's a good one.
You know what scares me
the most, Finn?
It scares me to think
that you might win this fight
and gain real power.
Doctor.
( sighs )
I...
I don't want you to fear me.
( equipment beeping )
( both groan )
( buzz of conversation )
The generator's
right over there.
MAN:
Were the power packs
distributed?
WOMAN:
Yes, sir.
Beverly, how dangerous
would another ride
through the
inverter be to us?
I don't know,
but I don't want you
to start thinking about...
Beverly, it is our obligation
to think of escape.
He's prepared
to kill you.
An excellent reason to escape.
Do you think you've
gained his confidence?
( paper rustles )
Indeed, you have.
And more.
This might prove
to be an advantage to us.
Jean-Luc...
There are some things
I want to tell you
in case we don't
get out of this.
Have they found us?
( alarm buzzing loudly )
MAN:
Right away!
WOMAN:
Look out.
MAN:
Samuel!
Come with me.
Do we have any emergency power?
Freeze!
Hold it right there!
Hands up.
Let's go.
Finn...
He's dead.
You didn't have
to kill him.
As a prisoner, he would have
been a focus for violence...
as his followers
tried to free him.
Now he's a martyr.
But the death toll
might go down,
at least,
in the short term.
It's an imperfect solution
for an imperfect world.
Riker!
No more killing.
Already another one
to take his place.
It never ends.
He could have killed you.
He didn't.
Maybe the end begins with
one boy putting down his gun.
I hear I owe
my rescue to you.
I was just part
of the team.
It's good
to have you back.
Both of you, sir.
Take us out of orbit,
Mr. Crusher.
PICARD:
At your convenience.