Captain's Log,
Stardate 43539.1.
We have moved into orbit
around Bre'el IV.
With the assistance
of the planet's
emergency control center
we are investigating
a catastrophic threat
to the population
from a descending
asteroidal moon.
( console beeping )
The satellite's trajectory
is continuing to
deteriorate, Captain.
This orbit will put it
within 500 kilometers
of the planet's surface.
We are predicting
the atmospheric drag
will bring it down
on the next orbit.
Have you been able to find
any explanation for this?
No, Doctor. It is a most
unusual phenomenon.
Won't the moon disintegrate
prior to impact?
No. It has a ferrous
crystalline structure
and it will be
able to withstand
tidal forces, Captain.
Could we blow it
into pieces?
The total mass of
the moon would remain
the same, Commander
and the impact of
thousands of fragments
would spread destruction
over an even wider area.
How long before impact?
29 hours, sir.
Projecting it somewhere
on the western continent.
That would destroy an area
800 kilometers in radius.
That damage would be
insignificant, Captain
compared to the
seismic repercussions
massive landquakes
and tsunami.
The force would raise a cloud
of dust around the planet
leading to a significant
temperature reduction.
We could be looking
at our own ice age.
Mr. La Forge, is there any way
that the Enterprise
could coax that satellite
back where it belongs?
We'd need to apply a delta-v
of about four kilometers
per second.
Even with warp power to the
tractor beam, it would mean
exceeding the recommended
impulse engine output
by at least 47%.
It would be like
an ant pushing a tricycle.
A slim chance at best.
Given the choice
between slim and none
I'll take slim any day.
Make it so.
Lieutenant Worf, contact
all ships in this sector
to rendezvous and join
us in relief efforts.
We'll keep you advised
of our progress.
Picard out.
Can you give us
any more, Geordi?
Not without burning out
the tractor beam emitter.
The circuits are already
beyond the thermal limit.
Delta-v
is 92 meters per second.
The mass is too great.
We are having an effect
but it is
negligible.
( metallic screeching )
What is that?
DATA:
Unable to
identify source!
Impulse engines
passing safety limits!
We're seconds
from automatic shutdown!
Reduce engine power,
tractor beam off!
Lieutenant Worf, what the
hell do the sensors say?!
The sound is not
registering, Commander!
Q.
Red Alert.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are no closer
to finding a solution
to the deteriorating orbit
of the Bre'el IV moon
but with the arrival of Q
we now have a good idea
of the cause.
Our options?
We've done everything
by the book and
a little extra.
We need more time or power,
and we're short on both.
I'll take a look and see
if there are any rules
I haven't broken.
Keep me informed.
We know you're behind this, Q.
These aren't my colors.
And what are you
blathering about, Riker?
What kind of
twisted pleasure
does it give you to bring
terror into their lives?
Whose lives?
The millions of
people down there
who are watching as their
moon falls out of the sky.
Oh, I haven't the vaguest idea
what you're talking about
and I have a much
more serious problem.
I'm no longer a member
of the Continuum.
My superiors have
decided to punish me.
And punish us as
well, it would seem.
They say I've spread chaos
through the universe
and they've stripped
me of all my powers.
You don't believe me, do you?
Do you think I would
humiliate myself like this?
If it served
your purpose, yes.
It's the truth.
I stand before you, defrocked.
Condemned to be a member
of this lowest of species--
a normal, imperfect,
lumpen human being.
They made you human
as part of your punishment?
No, it was my request.
I could have chosen to exist
as a Markoffian sea lizard
or a Belzoidian flea.
Anything I wished,
as long as it was mortal.
And since I had only
a fraction of a second to mull
I chose this
and asked them
to bring me here.
Why?
Because, in all the universe
you're the closest thing
I have to a friend, Jean Luc.
( tricorder humming )
DATA:
Sir
he is reading as fully human.
What, is there an echo in here?
TROI:
I am sensing
an emotional presence, Captain.
I would normally describe it
as being terrified.
How rude.
What is it you want, Q?
Your compassion.
All right,
sanctuary on this ship--
dreary as it may sound
to the both of us.
Return that moon to its orbit.
I have no powers!
Q, the ordinary.
Q, the liar,
Q, the misanthrope.
Q, the miserable.
Q, the desperate.
What must I do
to convince you people?
Die.
Oh, very clever, Worf.
Eat any good books lately?
Fine. You want to be
treated as human?
Absolutely.
All right.
Mr. Worf
throw him in the brig.
Delighted, Captain.
You can't do this
to me, Jean-Luc.
You will walk
or I will carry you.
Given the option,
I'll-I'll walk.
You've disappointed
me, Jean-Luc.
I'm very disappointed.
Hey, I'm claustrophobic.
I don't like it in here.
It was a mistake.
I never should have
picked human.
I knew it the moment I said it.
To think of a future
in this shell.
Forced to cover myself
with a fabric
because of some outdated
human morality--
to say nothing
of being too hot or too cold--
growing feeble with age,
losing my hair
catching a disease,
being ticklish, sneezing
having an itch,
a pimple, bad breath.
Having to bathe.
Too bad.
Klingon. I should
have said Klingon.
In my heart of hearts,
I am a Klingon, Worf.
Sorry.
So, you understand, I could
never survive in confinement.
I mean, this is cruel
and unusual punishment.
The universe
has been my backyard.
As a fellow Klingon
if you would speak to
the Captain on my behalf
I would be
eternally grateful.
Which doesn't
mean as much as it
used to, I admit.
Be quiet!
Or disappear back
where you came from!
I can't disappear
any more than you could
win a beauty contest.
If I were to ask you
a very simple question
do you think you might
be able to answer it
without it troubling
your intellect too much?
Ready?
Here goes.
Would I permit you to
lock me away if I still
had all my powers?
You have fooled us
too often, Q.
Oh, perspicacity incarnate.
Please don't feel
compelled now
to tell me the story of
the boy who cried "Worf."
Computer...
activate force field.
I demand to be let out of here.
Do you hear me?
You will deactivate
this cell immediately.
Romulan!
( growls quietly )
I should have said Romulan--
that Klingon goat.
The question is
what sort of jaded game
is he up to this time?
Maybe he just
wants a big laugh.
He'll take Bre'el IV
to the edge of disaster
and then pull
the moon back.
Or he may have nothing
to do with it at all.
You honestly think Q
is telling the truth?
Oh, I agree this
is highly unlikely
but we have to proceed
with our current dilemma
as though Q is powerless
to prevent it, don't we?
And there he sits and
he watches us struggle.
I don't see that we
have any choice.
Mr. Worf, will you hail the
Bre'el IV science station?
They're standing by, Captain.
BRE'EL DOCTOR:
Yes, Captain Picard?
I'm sorry, but I have to report
that our first attempt
to restore the moon
to its proper orbit
has failed.
( sighs )
We have less than 25 hours
before impact, Captain.
Our Chief Engineer
is working on ways
to reinforce
the tractor beam.
So, there is a hope
but if you have
an evacuation plan...
We have already
started moving people
from the coastal areas
of the western continent.
We are going to make
another attempt shortly.
Picard, out.
I've got to tell you, Geordi
is not at all optimistic.
What the devil...?
Data?
Sensors are showing
broadband emissions
including berthold rays.
Lethal?
No, Commander, overall exposure
is less than 75 rems.
Very low intensity.
More like a soft
medical scan.
I would speculate
we are being probed.
By whom?
Sensors cannot identify
the point of origin.
It seems to be coming
from all around us.
Ah, you've come
to apologize.
How nice.
All is forgiven.
No offense taken.
Enough.
Q, what exactly is going on?
Oh, but how can I know
what's going on?
I've been in this dungeon
of yours--
alone, helpless, bored to tears.
We have a moon, inexplicably
falling out of orbit
and just now this ship was
probed with berthold radiation.
I wasn't aware of this.
Truthfully, Jean-Luc.
I've been entirely preoccupied
by a most frightening
experience of my own.
A couple of hours ago,
I realized that my body
was no longer
functioning properly.
I felt weak.
I could
no longer stand.
The life was oozing out of me.
I lost consciousness.
You fell asleep.
Oh-- terrifying.
How can you stand it
day after day?
You get used to it.
What other dangers
await me?
I'm not prepared for this.
I need guidance.
Q, I'm not going
to play along with this.
If you want to continue this
charade, you can do it alone.
Jean-Luc, wait.
This is getting on my nerves,
now that I have them.
You have a moon in a
deteriorating orbit.
I've known moons
through the universe--
big ones, small ones.
I'm an expert.
I could help you with this one--
if you let me out of here.
Q, there are millions
of lives at risk.
If you have the power...
I don't have any powers.
But I have the knowledge
locked up in this puny brain.
You cannot afford to not take
that advantage, can you?
Mr. Data, report
to Detention Cell Three.
On my way, sir.
( sighs )
Computer, remove
the force field.
If you are human--
which I seriously doubt--
you will have to work hard
to earn our trust.
I'm not worried
about that, Jean-Luc.
You only dislike me.
There are others in the
cosmos who truly despise me.
Mr. Data, you are hereby
assigned to Q
for the remainder
of his stay.
You will escort him
to Mr. La Forge in Engineering.
Aye, sir.
Can I have a
Starfleet uniform?
What are you
looking at?
I was considering
the possibility
that you are
telling the truth--
that you really are human.
It's the ghastly
truth, Mr. Data.
I can now stub my toe
with the best of them.
An irony.
It means that you have achieved
in disgrace
what I have always aspired
to be.
Humans are such
commonplace
little creatures.
They roam the galaxy
searching for something,
they know not what.
The human race has
an enduring desire
for knowledge
and for new opportunities
to improve itself.
Well, there's certainly
room for improvement
but the truth is, Data,
they are a minor species
in the grand scheme--
not worth your envy.
Oh, I do not feel envy.
Well, that's good.
I feel nothing at all.
That is part
of my dilemma.
I have the curiosity
of humans
but there are questions
that I will never
have the answers to--
what it is like
to laugh or... or cry
or to experience
any human emotions.
Hmm.
Well, if you ask me,
these human emotions
are not what they're
cracked up to be.
Hmm.
The moon will hit
its perigee in ten hours.
Now, we match its trajectory,
increase emitter coolant rate
so that we can apply continuous
warp-equivalent power nine
to the tractor beam.
We can push it
for nearly seven hours
and I think
that just might do it.
But there's a problem.
The Enterprise will be
dangerously close
to the atmosphere.
That's the problem.
This is incredible.
You see something here, Q?
I think I just
hurt my back.
I'm feeling pain.
I don't like it.
What's the right
thing to say?
"Ow"?
Ow.
Ow!
I can't
straighten up.
Medical assistance
to Engineering.
Q, I've got a few people
down on Bre'el IV
who are going to be hurt...
Yes, yes, yes.
Your marvelous plan will not
only tear the moon to pieces
but your precious ship as well.
You got a better idea?
Well, I would certainly begin
by examining the cause
and not the symptom.
We've already done that, Q,
and there's no way to...
This is
obviously
the result of a large
celestial object
passing through
at near right angles
to the plane
of the star system--
probably a black hole.
DATA:
Can you recommend
a way to counter
the effect?
Simple. Change the
gravitational constant
of the universe.
What?
Change the gravitational
constant of the universe
thereby altering the
mass of the asteroid.
Redefine gravity.
And how am I supposed
to do that?
You just do it.
Oh! Where's that
doctor, anyway?
Geordi is trying to say
that changing the gravitational
constant of the universe
is beyond our capabilities.
Oh.
Well, in that case,
never mind.
Ah, Dr. Crusher.
I see Starfleet
has shipped you
back into exile.
Q says he has
hurt his back.
Uh-huh.
Well, if I didn't see it
with my own eyes
I wouldn't believe it.
According to this,
he has classic back trauma--
muscle spasms.
I've been under a lot
of pressure lately.
Family problems.
Mm. Well, don't expect
too much sympathy from me.
You have been a pain
in our backside often enough.
Ah! Oh.
Your bedside manner
is admirable, Doctor.
I'm sure your patients
recover quickly...
just to get away from you.
Oh!
You know, this might work.
We can't change
the gravitational
constant of the universe
but if we wrap a low-level
warp field around that moon
we could reduce its
gravitational constant--
make it lighter,
so we can push it.
Glad I could help.
Ow... I think.
Now what?
There's something wrong
with my stomach.
It hurts?
It's making noises.
Maybe you're hungry.
I've never eaten before.
What do I ask for?
The choice of meal
is determined by
individual taste.
What do you like?
Although I do not
require sustenance
I occasionally
ingest semi-organic
nutrient suspension
in a silicon-based
liquid medium.
Is it good?
It would be more
appropriate to say
it is good for me
as it lubricates
my bio-functions.
That doesn't sound
very appealing.
What else is there?
A wide variety of items.
The replicator can make
anything you desire.
How do I know
what I desire?
I have observed that
the selection of food
is often influenced
by the mood of the
person ordering.
I'm in a dreadful mood.
Get me something
appropriate.
When Counselor Troi
is unhappy
she usually eats
something chocolate.
Chocolate?
Mm-hmm.
A chocolate sundae,
for example.
Although I do not speak
from personal experience
I have seen it have a
profound psychological impact.
I'll have ten
chocolate sundaes.
Ten?
I have never
seen anyone eat
ten chocolate
sundaes.
I'm in a really bad mood.
And since I've never
eaten before, I should
be... very hungry.
( door opens and closes )
This is not a moment
I've been looking forward to.
I hear they drummed you
out of the Continuum.
I like to think of it
as a significant career change.
Just one of the boys, eh?
One of the boys
with an IQ of 2,005.
The Captain and many of the
crew are not yet convinced
he is truly human.
Really?
( yells in pain )
Seems human enough
to me.
This is
a dangerous creature.
You have no idea.
Why Picard would make her
a member of the crew
and not me...
It must be terribly
frightening for you to
be totally defenseless
after all of those centuries
of being omnipotent.
I'm warning you, I still
have friends in high places.
Frightening one race
after the other
teasing them like
frightened animals
and you enjoying every moment
of your victims' fears.
From now on, I'll do
missionary work, okay?
That would be a most
noble cause, Q.
You could learn a lot
from this one.
Sure-- the robot who teaches
the course in humanities.
I am an android,
not a robot.
I beg your pardon.
I'd enjoy that.
And you better get used to it.
What?
Begging.
You're a pitiful excuse
for a human.
The only way
you're going to survive
is on the charity
of others.
Oh, I'm not hungry.
Captain, sensors are picking up
a cloud of energetic plasma
bearing 341 mark 20.
Range-- 12 kilometers
and closing.
On screen.
Energy patterns are reading
as highly organized.
A life-form?
Attempt to make
contact, Mr. Worf.
Receiving a signal, sir.
On speaker.
( distorted voice-like static)
Computer,
analyze signal.
Signal patterns
indicate intelligence.
Unable to derive
necessary referents
to establish translation matrix.
( excited conversation )
Calamarain.
MAN:
Be careful!
( exclamations of concern )
( Q cries out in fear )
Captain, we're being hit
by a field
of energetic tachyons
penetrating the hull.
Location-- deck ten, forward.
Red Alert.
Geordi, increase power
to shields.
Increasing power by 20%.
No effect.
Increasing to 40%.
Still no effect.
( electric buzzing,
Q grunts in pain )
Adjusting shield harmonics.
Diverting power
to the forward grids.
The added harmonics
are blocking the tachyon field.
( groans in pain )
Help me!
Somebody, help me!
How the mighty have fallen.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have sustained light damage
from an attack
by an alien species
known as the Calamarain.
They apparently
have a grievance with Q--
no doubt one of many
life-forms that do.
The, uh, Calamarain are not
very hospitable creatures.
They exist as swirls
of ionized gas.
What did you
do to them, Q?
Oh, nothing bizarre.
Nothing grotesque.
You tormented them.
A subjective term, Riker.
One creature's torment is
another creature's delight.
They simply have
no sense of humor.
A character flaw with which you
can... personally identify.
I say we turn him over to them.
Oh, well, I take it back.
You do you have
a sense of humor--
a dreadful one at that.
I'm serious.
Of course.
You knew this would happen,
didn't you?
One can never anticipate
the Calamarain.
They're very intelligent,
but very flighty.
Yes, but you
must have
so many enemies.
Certainly you knew
that if once you became mortal
some of them might look you up.
It had occurred to me.
Mm-hmm.
And for all your protestations
of "friendship"
your real reason
for being here is protection.
( chuckles )
You're very smart, Jean-Luc.
But I know human beings.
They're all sopping over
with compassion
and forgiveness.
They can't wait
to absolve almost any offense.
It's an inherent weakness
of the breed.
On the contrary,
it is a strength.
You call it what you will,
but I think you'll protect me
even though I've tormented you
now and again.
Fighting off all the species
which you have insulted
would be a full-time mission.
That's not the one
I signed up for.
Indeed.
Human or not,
I want no part of you.
We will deposit you
at the first starbase.
Let them deal with you.
Uh-uh, but I could be
a valuable member of the team.
I'm human.
I can learn.
He has provided important
theoretical guidance
for Geordi's analysis of the
Bre'el satellite, Captain.
It seems you have
an advocate, Q.
I am merely stating the fact,
Counselor.
Mr. La Forge, your status?
I've been putting together
a program
to extend the forward lobe
of the warp field.
The field coils aren't designed
to envelope such a large volume
but I'm attempting to modify
their alignment parameters.
DATA:
Maintaining field integrity
will be difficult, Geordi.
Well, I'm pretty sure
that we can do it manually.
The moon will come
to its perigee in 14 minutes.
Mr. Data, you will escort Q
to Engineering.
You will assist Mr. La Forge.
Mr. Worf, hail the Bre'el IV
science station.
Aye, sir.
Picard thinks I can't cut it
on his starship.
I can do anything
his little trained
minions can do.
I do not perceive your
skills to be in doubt, Q.
The Captain is merely
concerned with your ability
to successfully interact with
"his little trained minions."
Human interpersonal
relationships are
more complex.
Your experience may not have
adequately prepared you.
I'm not interested in human
interpersonal relationships.
I just want to prove to Picard
that I'm indispensable.
Engineering.
To function aboard
a starship, or in
any human activity
you must learn to
form relationships.
( sighing ):
It's so hard.
And of more
immediate importance
is your ability
to work within groups.
I'm not good in groups.
It's difficult
to work in a group
when you're omnipotent.
The tides reached 10 meters
on the last orbit.
They are already beginning
to swell again.
We have a lot of frightened
people down here, Captain.
Your moon has begun moving
towards its perigee.
We're preparing
to make our attempt.
Our population has
already taken shelter
but I'm afraid no shelter
will be adequate if you fail
especially for the people
on the western continent.
Whatever the results
we know you've
done your best, Picard.
It's appreciated.
We'll keep you advised, Doctor.
Picard out.
Captain, sensors are picking up
an increased energy output
from the Calamarain.
La Forge to Bridge.
The moon has reached
its minimum orbital distance.
It's time, Captain.
We'll have
to lower shields.
Proceed.
Mr. Worf, keep a close eye
on Q's friends out there.
Understood.
All right, everyone, this is
what we're going to be doing...
Q, everybody already knows
what they're going to do,
except for you.
Now, here's
what I need...
La Forge, obviously,
my knowledge
and experience
far exceeds yours
by about a billion times.
So, if you'll just step
aside gracefully.
Q, Your experience will
be most valuable to me
if you can manually
control the field integrity.
Don't be foolish.
That would be a waste
of my talents.
Q, get to the controls
or get the hell out of here!
Data, you're my liaison
to the Bridge.
I'll need you with me.
Who does he think he
is, giving me orders?
Geordi thinks
he is in command here
and he is correct.
Engineering, holding at station
keeping, range 640 meters.
DATA:
Containment fields
to flight tolerance.
Warp core to 90%.
Engage field coils,
tractor beam to stand-by.
Field output?
( bored ):
Two-seventeen.
Impulse engines to full.
Ready to engage tractor beam.
Lowering shields,
engage tractor beam.
Extending warp field forward.
PICARD:
Engineering, is that
the forward limit?
Yes, Captain, we are unable
to encompass the entire moon.
Do you recommend
that we proceed?
The two parts of the moon
will have different
inertial densities.
Stand by, Captain.
I can adjust the field symmetry
to compensate.
I doubt it.
You don't know
what this ship can do, mister.
Yes, Captain,
I still believe it'll work.
Increasing power to warp field
and tractor beam.
And if you're wrong
the moon will crumble
due to subspace compression.
Don't say
I didn't warn you.
Shut up, Q.
I will not be spoken to
in this manner!
Data.
Q, I strongly suggest
that you cooperate.
Inertial mass of
the moon is decreasing
to approximately
2.5 million metric tons.
It is working.
We can move it.
Firing impulse engines.
DATA:
Captain, the moon's trajectory
has moved .3 percent.
.4 percent.
Emergency!
Shields up.
Disengage
tractor beam.
Calamarain attacking.
( alarm blaring )
Shields holding.
Tachyon field repelled.
LA FORGE:
Captain, the impact of the blast
is pushing us
into the upper atmosphere.
Hull temperature
rising-- 2,000 degrees
2,500 degrees.
LA FORGE:
Moving to full impulse power.
WORF:
Calamarain resuming attack.
They've overpowered the shields.
Hull penetration, deck 36--
Engineering.
Geordi, can you direct
anymore power to the shields?
We need all the power we have
to get out of the atmosphere,
Commander.
( whooshing whir )
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Get off!
No, no, no, no, no!
( yelling )
Try activating
the structural integrity field.
Yes, sir.
( straining groans )
It's not working.
Structural field harmonics
on manual.
( electronic buzzing )
RIKER:
La Forge, hull temperature
falling.
We're in the clear.
Diverting power
to forward sections now.
( yells )
( electronic crackling )
That charge nearly knocked out
his positronic net.
What can you do for him?
We can try to discharge
and reset the motor pathways
recouple the
autonomic nodes...
There's overpressure
in his fluidic systems.
Thermal shock.
If he was mortal,
he'd be dead.
Well, let's not overstate
the matter here, Doctor.
I'm mortal and I survived.
Oh, the cheers
are overwhelming.
Q, you exceed
your own standards
of self-preoccupation.
You have no concern
for an officer
who may have
saved your life.
He's strong.
He'll survive.
LA FORGE:
Osmotic pressure
still rising.
Maybe we can bypass
the flow regulator.
It would be helpful if everybody
just got out of here now.
Stay with Q.
Geordi?
Hmm?
The moon's trajectory.
All we did was buy ourselves
another orbit-- at most.
We can try again
when the moon comes
back to its perigee.
And when we drop our shields
the Calamarains
go after Q again.
Commander, he's
not worth it.
( door chimes )
Come.
You're right, of course.
I'm extraordinarily
selfish
but it has served me
so well in the past.
It will not
serve you here.
Don't be so hard
on me, Jean-Luc.
You've been a mortal
all your life.
You know all about dying.
I've never given it
a second thought.
Or a first one,
for that matter.
I could have been killed.
If it hadn't been for Data
and that one brief
delay he created
I would have
been gone.
No more me.
And no one would have missed me
would they?
Data may have sacrificed
himself for me.
Why?
That is his special nature.
He learned the lessons
of humanity well.
When I ask myself if I would
have done the same for him
and I am forced to answer no
I feel... I feel ashamed.
Q, I am not
your father confessor.
You will receive
no absolution from me.
You have brought nothing but
pain and suffering to this crew.
And I am still
not entirely convinced
that all this isn't your latest
attempt at a puerile joke.
It is a joke, a joke on me--
joke of the universe,
the king who would be man.
As I learn
more and more
what it is to be human,
I am more and more convinced
that I would never
make a good one.
I don't have what it takes.
Without my powers,
I'm frightened of everything.
I'm a coward.
And I'm miserable.
And I can't go on this way.
( door opens and closes )
He's going
to be all right.
LA FORGE:
We're re-calibrating
his language circuits,
so he can't talk yet.
There are creatures
in the universe
who would consider you the
ultimate achievement, android.
No feelings, no emotions,
no pain--
and yet you covet
those qualities of humanity.
Believe me,
you're missing nothing.
But if it means anything to you,
you're a better human than I.
Where's the main shuttle bay?
Main shuttle bay is located
on deck four.
Take me there.
( console beeping )
Captain, an unscheduled shuttle
has just been launched.
On main viewer.
Hailing frequency.
Frequency's open.
Shuttle occupant,
identify yourself.
Don't try and talk me out of it,
Jean-Luc.
Q, return to the ship
immediately.
I just can't get used
to following orders.
Captain, the plasma cloud
is moving toward the shuttle.
It's easier this way.
They won't bother you
after I'm gone.
Engineering, prepare
to extend shields.
Please, don't fall back
on your tired clich
of charging to the rescue
just in the nick of time.
I don't want to be rescued.
My life as a human being
has been a dismal failure.
Perhaps my death
will have a little dignity.
Q, there is no dignity
in this suicide.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Death of a coward, then,
so be it.
But as a human,
I would have died of boredom.
This goes against
my better judgment.
Transporter Room Three,
lock on to Shuttle One.
Beam it back into its bay.
Aye, Captain.
It's a perfectly
good shuttlecraft.
Captain, unable to transport.
For some reason, I can't lock on
to the shuttlecraft.
Worf, are you sensing
any interference
from the Calamarain?
No, sir, but they are still
moving toward the shuttle.
Geordi, extend shields
around Shuttle One.
Extending shields.
Commander,
the shields are frozen.
RIKER:
Cause?
Unknown.
Lock on tractor beam.
Tractor beam is not functioning,
either.
What the hell is going on?
MALE VOICE:
Not bad, Q.
Not great...
( sighs )
but not bad.
Q!
Ah!
Sacrificing yourself
for these humans?
Do I detect
a little selfless act?
You flatter me.
I was only trying to put
a quick end
to a miserable existence.
( groans )
What a dreadful color.
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I've been
keeping track of you.
I always thought
you were in my corner.
Ah, no, no.
See, actually, I was the one
who got you kicked out.
You know, you're
incorrigible, Q.
You're a lost cause.
I can't go
to a single solar system
without having
to... apologize for you
and I'm tired of it.
I wasn't the one who misplaced
the entire
Deltived asteroid belt.
Hey, this isn't about me.
I got better places to be.
But somebody had to keep
an eye on you to make sure
you still didn't find a way
to cause trouble.
Even as a member
of this...
hmm... limited species.
Well, I... I hope
I've been entertaining you.
Barely.
But... I find these humans
rather interesting.
I'm beginning to understand
what you see in them.
After all the things
that you've done
they're still intent
on keeping you safe.
A genetic weakness
of the race.
And they're still at it.
They just tried to... mmm...
beam you up, back
whatever it is they call it.
Really.
I stopped them.
Well, if the Calamarains
hurry up and finish me off
we can get you back
on your way.
Afraid I had to put
them on hold, too.
You see, there's still this
matter of the selfless act.
Now, you and I both know
that the Calamarain
would have
eventually destroyed
the Enterprise
to get to you
and that's really
why you left, right?
It was a teeny bit selfless,
wasn't it?
Oh! Yeah, and
there's my problem.
See, I can't go back
to the Continuum
and tell them
that you committed
a selfless act
just before the end.
If I do, there's going
to be questions
there's going to be explanations
for centuries.
I've learned my lesson, Q.
Remember who
you're talking to--
all knowing, all seeing.
( sighs )
Hmm, fine.
Oh... you got your powers back.
Try and stay out of trouble.
So they wanted to destroy me,
did they?
If you think I tormented you
in the past, my little friends
wait until you see
what I do with you now.
Q...?
I was just seeing
if you were still watching.
Captain,
the aliens have disappeared
and so has the shuttle.
Scan the sector.
I have, sir.
Well... I suppose
that is the end of Q.
Au contraire,
mon capitaine!
He's back!
( playing mariachi music )
I'm forgiven.
My brothers and sisters
of the Continuum
have taken me back.
I'm immortal again,
omnipotent again.
Swell.
Don't fret, Riker.
My good fortune
is your good fortune.
I don't need your fantasy women.
Oh, you're so stolid.
You weren't like that
before the beard.
( sighs )
Very well.
Q!
But I feel like celebrating.
I don't!
All right.
All of it.
Oh...
Now, at the risk
of being rude...
Yes, once again,
I've overstayed
my welcome.
As a human,
I was ill-equipped to thank you
but, as myself, you have
my everlasting gratitude.
Until next time.
Ah, but, before I go,
there's a debt I wish to repay
to my professor
of the humanities.
Data, I've decided
to give you something
very, very special.
If your intention is
to make me human, Q...
No, no, no, no, no.
I would never curse you
by making you human.
Think of it...
as a going-away present.
( laughing uproariously )
LA FORGE:
Data...?
Data, why are
you laughing?
It...
I do not know.
But it was a wonderful...
feeling.
( console beeping )
Captain, Bre'el IV
is hailing us.
On screen,
Lieutenant.
Captain Picard,
you've done it.
I'm sorry?
The moon-- it's back
to its normal orbit.
However you did
it, thank you.
Let's see it, Worf.
Mr. Data, your analysis?
The moon's altitude
is 55,000 kilometers.
Projected orbit is circular.
There is no further danger
to the planet.
Ensign, set course
for Station Nigala IV.
Aye, sir.
Perhaps there's a... residue
of humanity in Q after all.
Ensign, en...
Don't bet
on it, Picard.