Captain, we have arrived
at Tanuga IV.
The away team has completed
its survey of Dr. Apgar's work
and is ready to return
to the ship.
Good.
Oh, please... and feel free
to examine the work
of the other students, too.
Hmm...
Ensign Williams'
striking style
is heavily influenced
by geometric
constructivism.
Lieutenant Wright has
effectively fused
the incongruities
of the surrealists
with the irrationality
of Dadaism.
Interesting.
Oh.
Thank you.
In what way?
While suggesting
the free treatment of form
usually attributed to fauvism
this quite inappropriately
attempts to juxtapose
the disparate
cubistic styles of
Picasso and Leger.
In addition, the use of color
suggests a haphazard melange
of clashing styles.
Furthermore,
the unsettling
overtones
of proto-Vulcan
influences...
Thank you... Mr. Data.
You are welcome, sir.
If I can be of
further assistance...
No... thank you.
( door opens and closes )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43610.4:
After completing a delivery
of dicosilium
to the Tanuga IV
research station
our away team has received
an update from Dr. Nel Apgar
on his efforts
to create Krieger waves,
a potentially valuable
new power source.
Welcome back,
Mr. La Forge.
Thank you, sir.
Where's Commander Riker?
He's still down
on the station, sir.
Dr. Apgar wanted
to have a word with him.
Any problems?
Not with the scientific part
of the mission, no, sir.
Riker to Enterprise.
I'm ready to leave now.
I'm sure Commander Riker
will be able
to explain
everything, Captain.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by, Commander.
Engaging transport.
( beeping )
( machinery powering down )
Transporter Room to Engineering.
I have a power drain.
Transporter Room.
Is Commander Riker aboard?
O'BRIEN:
Not yet, Captain. I'm having
trouble clearing the signal.
Transporter Room to Bridge.
He's aboard.
Why do you sound
so surprised, Mr. O'Brien?
Well, for a moment,
we weren't sure
you left the space
station in time.
In time for what?
It just exploded, sir.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental:
Commander Riker has informed me
that Dr. Apgar was the only one
aboard the space station
when it exploded.
We remain in orbit
investigating the accident.
I've gone through
the whole system, Captain.
I can't find any malfunction
in the transporter
or nothing that would cause
an explosion like that.
Why was there
a power drain
before transport?
I don't know, sir.
I shall want an
answer to that.
I'm sure the
Tanugans will, too.
Yes, sir.
Captain, the radiation
and debris
are consistent with an overload
of the station's reactor core.
Were there
any indications
of reactor
core problems
while you were
on the station?
No, sir.
Number One?
Mr. La Forge indicated
that this was not
an entirely routine mission.
It's a long story, sir
but I'm sure it doesn't have
anything to do
with this accident.
( communications beep )
Captain, Chief Investigator Krag
of the Tanugan security force
requests permission
to beam aboard.
Granted. Will you
escort him to the
Bridge, Mr. Worf?
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Perhaps you had better tell me
as much as possible
prior to his arrival,
Number One.
( sighing )
I'm Lieutenant Worf,
head of ship's security.
I will take you to the Captain.
Chief Investigator,
welcome to
the Enterprise.
I'm Captain Picard.
This is my
First Officer
Commander
William Riker.
Commander Riker, I am here
to take you into custody.
Custody? On what charge?
Suspicion of murder.
Murder? Now, wait a minute.
You can't come on...
Chief Investigator...
we are perfectly willing
to cooperate with you...
Then release the prisoner
for transportation
to the planet.
Let's continue this
discussion in private.
Number One, you
have the Bridge.
Just what is the evidence
against my officer?
Two witnesses have come forward
to describe Commander Riker's
threats against Dr. Apgar.
Threats?
I'm aware there was
a private conversation
between them.
Apparently, it was much more
than just a private conversation
but he will be given a chance
to prove his innocence.
Investigator, in our system
of jurisprudence,
a man is innocent
until proved guilty.
In ours, he is guilty
until he is proved innocent,
and you are under
our jurisdiction.
If I understand Federation
regulations on this matter,
and I just happened
to look them up...
I am aware of Federation
regulations, sir,
and if you investigate
them further
you will find
the Captain decides
if extradition
is warranted.
Are you saying it is not?
I am saying
if there is sufficient cause
to warrant a trial,
I will release my officer
into your custody.
Would you say that you are close
to your First Officer, Captain?
That question
is irrelevant here.
Really, Captain,
you cannot believe that.
How can I expect
a fair and impartial decision?
I must protect the
rights of my officer.
I can appreciate that,
but you will do it
on the planet, not here.
After all, what if you
were suddenly to decide
to leave this star system?
You have my word
as a Starfleet officer
that I will not.
Unacceptable.
Captain, you will turn him over
to me for interrogation now.
Interrogate him here.
We must re-create step by step,
moment by moment,
all the events
leading to the explosion.
We will require access
to all the witnesses
as well as the data
from the lab's ground computers.
It would be impossible
to accomplish here.
Perhaps not.
Mr. Data, will you report
to my ready room?
DATA: Aye, sir.
We may be able to assist you
in re-creating these events.
Commander Data, this is
Chief Inspector Krag.
Commander, by
taking testimony
from the away team
and from witnesses provided
by the Investigator,
would it be possible
to program the holodeck
to re-create what happened
on the science station?
It would require construction
and design specifications
full orthographic
representations
of the Krieger equipment
as well as visual
representations
and voice analyses
of the persons involved,
but it is possible.
Very well.
Arrangements will be
made to provide you
with all available
information.
I shall return shortly
with our witnesses.
Commander, will you escort
Investigator Krag
to Transporter Room Three?
Ensign Crusher,
Mr. La Forge...
we are going
to re-create the
research station
here on the holodeck.
I want you to work
with Commander Data
on the preparations.
In addition,
Commander La Forge
and Commander Riker,
I want you to
give the computer
detailed depositions
of everything you saw,
everything you heard
while you were on board.
Counselor, I want
you to assist me
during this inquiry.
My decision about
the extradition will be based
on the evidence presented
during these re-creations.
Captain...
May I have a word with you?
Under the circumstances,
Number One,
I think that would be
inappropriate.
DATA:
Second Officer's Log,
Stardate 43611.6:
Programming of the holodeck
has taken 18 hours, 11 minutes
and is now complete.
All participants have entered
their depositions.
Technical schematics
and complete records
from the lab's
ground computers
as well as Dr. Apgar's
personal logs
have been included.
The re-creations will have
a nominal 8.7%
margin of error.
( door begins closing )
Is there anything
you'd like to say
before we begin,
Number One?
Just this.
I'm not a murderer.
I went to the
Tanugan lab
as an official
representative
of Starfleet.
I acted accordingly.
I was there to evaluate
Dr. Apgar's progress
in the development
of a Krieger-wave
converter.
That's all I was
interested in.
Computer...
( beeping )
...load deposition program
Riker One.
Run the simulation.
Dr. Apgar?
I'm Commander
William Riker.
Lieutenant Commander
Geordi La Forge.
My assistant, Tayna.
Well, let's get on
with it, shall we?
Let's not be in
such a hurry, dear.
Perhaps our guest
would care for
some refreshments?
My wife, Manua.
RIKER:
A pleasure to meet you,
Mrs. Apgar.
If you're prepared to start,
so are we.
Of course,
I'm prepared.
All right. Why
don't you give me
an overview of
your research
while Mr. La Forge
and your assistant
take a look at the
experimental data.
Fine, whatever.
I must say, Commander, I
resent this early arrival.
Starfleet will get
its converter.
I've had a few
setbacks, that's all.
We're not here to
pressure you, Doctor.
We just want an update
on your progress.
Tayna, show the
Commander's assistant
whatever he wants to
see. Give him full
access to our records.
TAYNA:
Yes, Doctor.
If you'll
come with me.
Our lambda
field generator
is on the planet
since it requires
a minimum
of 5,000 kilometers
for the field
to collimate.
Really, darling,
you're being rude.
After all,
Commander Riker is willing
to sit through all your prattle
about Krieger waves.
Let's have a drink, Commander,
and we'll hear
all about Krieger waves.
To your success, Doctor.
Mm-hmm.
And the rewards
that come with it.
Riker, what is Starfleet
doing here anyway?
My delivery wasn't scheduled
for another three months.
Well, we were in this sector
on another mission,
and since you had already
contacted Starfleet
about additional dicosilium,
it seemed like
a good opportunity.
How interesting.
Tell us about
this other mission.
It was just a study
of a proto-star cloud.
The Enterprise
will be back tomorrow.
just left you here?
We didn't want
to inconvenience you.
We've made arrangements
for quarters on the planet.
Oh, I won't hear
of such a thing.
Commander, I insist you
and Mr. La Forge stay with us.
I hardly think...
I know that you would prefer
to be left alone
with your very
important work
but I, for one,
am glad for the company.
Good.
I must apologize
for my husband's lack
of social graces.
He may be one
of the great scientific minds
in the galaxy, but...
he does come up a bit short
in other areas.
KRAG:
Wait a moment.
Stop.
Computer,
freeze program.
KRAG:
Then it's your testimony
that it was
Mrs. Apgar's idea
for you to spend the night
aboard the space station?
It's my testimony
and it's the truth.
Resume program.
Our guest quarters
aren't luxurious,
but I've tried
to make this room
warm and inviting.
I'll be very
comfortable, thank you.
Good night.
The environmental
controls are over here.
I'm sure I'll find
everything I need.
And the door shuts
by touching this panel.
Mrs. Apgar...
This is my sanctuary.
Privacy is very important
on a small station.
I'm left alone here,
often for hours.
It's late.
I am tired.
Are you still tired,
Commander?
RIKER:
Ma'am, excuse me.
I really think
that you ought to leave.
I knew I'd find you
with him.
Did you think I didn't notice
how you looked at him?
I'm not the fool
you take me for.
RIKER:
Doctor!
( groaning )
Doctor, believe me.
This has been
a terrible mistake.
You won't get away with this.
I'll see to it.
I swear I
will, Riker.
Freeze program.
I didn't
see Dr. Apgar
until the
following morning
when he asked
to see me alone.
Commander La Forge
returned to the
Enterprise.
Resume program.
I suppose if I make
a formal complaint,
your report on my work
won't be very good.
Doctor, this is going to have
no impact on my report.
It was a misunderstanding
of the worst kind.
We could straighten
the entire thing out
if you would ask
Mrs. Apgar to join us.
My wife and
my assistant
have transported
down to the planet.
What are you going
to put in your
report, Riker?
That there is
no justification
for all the
extra dicosilium
I've requested?
That is why they sent
you early, isn't it?
Doctor, I...
NEL:
I can explain
why I needed it.
They have no idea
what my problems are.
There are
explanations for...
I don't need
explanations.
Then we have nothing further
to say to each other.
I'll tell my Captain
to expect your grievance.
Do that.
Riker to Enterprise.
I'm ready to leave now.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by, Commander.
Engaging transport.
Freeze program.
Then I returned
to the Enterprise.
And you have nothing further
to add, Commander?
Nothing about firing a phaser?
I never fired a phaser
on the science station.
Well, that's odd... very odd.
Captain Picard, is it not true
that your sensors
detected an energy drain
just as Commander Riker
began transport?
That's correct.
KRAG:
Have you been able
to explain it?
PICARD:
Not to my knowledge.
We have.
Our readings are
quite clear about it.
Information retrieved
from the lab's ground computers
indicate that a focused
energy pulse was fired
just as Commander Riker
began transport.
Furthermore, by analyzing
the angle and trajectory,
we have determined that
it came from the very spot
Commander Riker was standing.
So then, will you allow me
to show you my re-creation
of the end of this story?
A speculation,
if you will.
Computer...
run hypothetical Krag one.
Riker to Enterprise.
I'm ready to leave now.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by, Commander.
Engaging transport.
KRAG:
Freeze program.
Three seconds later,
the space station exploded.
LA FORGE:
The Tanugans are right.
Something was fired
at the reactor core
just before transport.
The energy signature
would seem to indicate
a phaser-like blast.
Well, it wasn't
the Commander's phaser.
It couldn't have been.
There's another answer.
We're just not seeing it.
Was there anything
else in the lab
capable of creating this
kind of energy discharge?
Not that I saw.
Besides, how do you
account for the fact
that it came from
Commander Riker's
exact position?
Damn it, I should've
stayed with him.
( beeping )
Commander.
Sensors indicate
a radiation burst
on deck 39
outside cargo bay 12.
Source?
Unknown, sir.
Computer, identify
type of radiation.
Emission is not consistent
with any known radiation.
It is subsiding, sir.
WESLEY:
What kind of radiation
could do this?
Make any sense to you?
I don't recognize it.
Not even the main deflector
puts out that kind of spillage.
Where would it
be coming from?
I don't know, Wes,
but whatever it is
it's capable of putting
a hole in solid duranium.
In a sense,
we have already
met Mrs. Apgar,
so we shall dispense
with introductions.
PICARD:
Mrs. Apgar,
you understand the
purpose of this hearing?
TROI:
We understand
how difficult
this will be for you.
If you need a recess,
please don't
hesitate to ask.
PICARD:
Would you like
to make a statement
before we begin?
No.
I just know he did it.
He killed my husband.
Computer,
load Manua
Simulation One.
Run program.
If you greet them
with such a long face
they're going to assume
something is wrong
with the experiment.
I just need time,
a little more time.
I'm certain they'll give you
all the time you need
if you just show
a little charm.
You do that so much better
than I do.
Manua, someday I'll be able
to reward you
for all
your patience.
I'll get you everything
you ever dreamed of.
I have all the reward I need.
Now go on.
I'll be right in.
( door opens and closes )
RIKER:
Dr. Apgar?
I'm Commander
William Riker.
Lieutenant Commander
Geordi La Forge.
My assistant, Tayna.
Well, let's get on
with it, shall we?
Don't be in such a hurry, dear.
Perhaps our guests would
like some refreshment?
My wife, Manua.
A pleasure
to meet you, Manua.
NEL:
I'm anxious
to get started.
If you wish.
I must say, I resent your
early arrival, Commander.
I have much work to do.
Doctor, I'll
do everything
in my power
to make this as painless
as possible for both of us.
Do you assist
your husband
in his work?
Oh, dear, no,
I'm no scientist.
No, neither am I.
But I find this all fascinating,
don't you?
Mr. La Forge, why
don't you take a look
at the Doctor's
experimental data.
Later you can
give me an overview.
Fine, whatever.
Starfleet will get its
Krieger-wave converter.
These things take time.
I've had a few setbacks,
that's all.
RIKER:
Doctor, I'm not trying to put
any pressure on you.
I'm sure my report will
only underscore the need
for continued support
of your research.
Mm-hmm.
Tayna,
I'll call up
the records.
Show the Commander's
assistant whatever
he wants to see.
Yes, Doctor. If
you'll come with me.
Our field generator
is on the planet
since it requires a minimum
of 5,000 kilometers
for the field
to collimate.
Darling, let Tayna
take care of that.
I'm sure
Commander Riker
wants to hear how
close you are to
a breakthrough.
I'll pour the two
of you a drink
and you can talk all
about Krieger waves.
Commander.
To success.
Success.
Well, in a way, I suppose
it's good that you're early.
Manua's right.
It gives me a
chance to show you
the progress
we've been making.
I would appreciate it
if Commander La Forge and I
could stay here
until the Enterprise returns.
It's a little inconvenient.
It would help
to accelerate the process.
Well, if you wish, Commander.
Now, uh...
where shall I start?
Well, first of all,
you should know
that I am very close
to being able to collimate
a Krieger field.
Our guest quarters
are quite modest.
RIKER:
Very charming.
It has your touch.
The station is small
and we don't often have guests,
so I use this
as my sanctuary.
Who do you need
sanctuary from?
The environmental
controls are here.
( sighing )
Commander, please...
it's late and I'm tired.
A man more interested
in Krieger waves
than a lovely woman like you...
How is that possible?
My husband is one
of the greatest minds
in the galaxy,
and we love each other
very much.
Please, don't.
RIKER:
You must be very lonely...
a princess
in a very high tower.
Please, my husband
will be looking for me.
Your sanctuary, remember?
Commander, don't, please!
She's lying.
That never happened.
Freeze program.
Please...
Captain, you know I would
never act like that.
Commander Riker...
This isn't me.
I wasn't the one
who closed the door.
I didn't proposition her
and I certainly didn't
try to rape her.
Why are you
doing this?
It's exactly what happened.
Will, come on, sit down.
Resume program.
Please...
I knew you'd try this, Riker.
Do you think I didn't notice
how you looked at her?
I'm not the fool
you take me for.
You won't get
away with this.
Your career is over.
I'll see to it,
I swear I will, Riker.
If you report this,
you'll be making
a terrible mistake, Doctor.
A terrible mistake.
Freeze program.
Your career was safe.
He was a scientist.
In another day,
some fascinating bit
of technical trivia
would have distracted him.
He would have forgotten
about you
and his complaint
to Starfleet.
( softly ):
Excuse me.
We'll, um...
we'll take a short recess.
Why would she lie like that?
She was lying.
You could tell.
Will, I didn't sense
any deception from her.
Then you think
that I would...?
No! No, of course not.
I know you.
You don't have
to convince me
of anything.
We can't both be
telling the truth.
It is the truth as
each of you remembers it.
But her version
puts a noose around my neck.
This is healing
beautifully.
I think you can
work on strengthening
those muscles again.
WORF:
Security to Dr. Crusher.
( alarm blaring )
Evacuate. Repeat, evacuate.
Radiation emissions
are indicated in Sick Bay.
( alarm continues )
This is definitely
the same radiation
that penetrated deck 39.
Highly focused, very powerful,
but of unknown origin.
If this should happen
near the engine core
or the antimatter
containment tanks,
we'll be in
big trouble, Captain.
Do you have any theories?
Captain, Data's
noticed something
that's too strange
to be a coincidence.
The two radiation events
aboard the Enterprise
occurred five hours, 20 minutes
and three seconds apart.
The science station exploded
yesterday
at almost four times
that interval.
WESLEY:
There's a .0014-second variance
we haven't been able
to explain yet.
So you're saying
there's a connection
between the radiation bursts
and the explosion.
We do not have the evidence
to support that conclusion
at this time, Commander.
BEVERLY:
If they're right,
we should be able to
predict the next event.
We're expecting it
in just over five hours.
Well, take every precaution
to protect the ship's
vital areas.
If we haven't identified
the source
before the next time interval,
we'll leave orbit.
If you perceive
any further danger,
advise me immediately.
We'll figure it out
for you, Commander.
After the... the fight,
Dr. Apgar came to find me.
He was very upset.
And he told you what happened?
Yes, he told me everything
that happened.
Based on Tayna's deposition,
we have re-created the incident
in Commander Riker's quarters
as Dr. Apgar described it
to her.
Computer...
Inspector, Inspector,
this is hearsay.
She wasn't a witness
to this incident.
But Dr. Apgar is dead.
Her statement is admissible
according to Tanugan law
and I insist you
consider it.
Well... we'll watch
this "evidence"
and we'll weigh it
accordingly.
Computer, run Tayna
Simulation Three.
I knew I'd find
the two of you together.
Do you think
I didn't notice
how you were looking
at each other?
I'm not the fool
you take me for.
I'm going to report this,
Riker.
You can count on that.
You're a dead man, Apgar.
A dead man.
Freeze program.
And then Dr. Apgar
came to find you?
Yes.
Run Tayna Simulation Four.
I want you to take Manua
and beam down to
Tanuga immediately.
But, Doctor,
if he threatened you
you shouldn't stay.
I'm not leaving him
here alone.
He's capable
of anything.
I've got to
protect our work.
I'll contact
the authorities.
No... I'll take
care of that.
Doctor, be careful.
It'll be all right.
Go on.
KRAG:
Freeze program.
Then what happened?
I left the station
with Manua.
The next day, when I heard
the station had exploded,
I knew what had happened.
He'd killed Dr. Apgar.
KRAG:
Thank you.
You are excused.
( door opens and closes )
Captain, I have
established motive,
method and opportunity.
In any court
in the Federation
that is sufficient
to warrant the extradition
of the accused.
I await your
decision forthwith.
I don't see
any alternative.
Do you?
We both know Will's innocent.
Of course he's innocent!
But as a Starfleet Captain,
I can't allow myself the luxury
of yielding
to personal feelings.
The evidence warrants a trial.
I'll have to allow extradition.
Do you think
there's enough evidence
to prove his innocence?
No.
DATA:
Captain, I believe we have found
the source of the radiation.
Can you join us on the Bridge?
Acknowledged.
As you know, Captain,
we are looking for
a phenomenon
that reoccurs
every five hours
20 minutes and
three seconds.
The interval between
the radiation bursts.
We have found one
such phenomenon
on the
planet surface.
It's the field generator
that Apgar used
during his research.
When it's fully charged
it automatically emits
an energy pulse
and then takes five hours
20 minutes and three seconds
to recharge itself.
It must have been left on
after the explosion at the lab.
But why would
a generator
be affecting the
Enterprise in this way?
It should not be.
It is a harmless
lambda field generator.
LA FORGE:
But we knew that somehow
it was related
to our radiation bursts,
and then the pieces
just started falling together.
We now know
what is causing the bursts
and why the science station
exploded, sir.
And we also know
who killed Dr. Apgar.
Chief Inspector,
we've watched these events
replayed over and over again
and... I am impressed
and admittedly dismayed
by the body of evidence
against Commander Riker.
But isn't it remarkable
that with all the witnesses,
all the different points
of view
of the events
aboard the space station,
we haven't seen
what really happened?
I do not understand.
Allow me, with the help
of Mr. La Forge, to explain.
Computer, load
Manua Program One,
time index 14-4-1.
Play program.
Fine, whatever.
Starfleet will get
its Krieger-wave converter.
These things take time.
I've had a few setbacks,
that's all.
PICARD:
Freeze.
Mrs. Apgar, this
is taken from
your deposition.
It would seem to suggest
that your husband
had failed to create
Krieger waves.
Yes, but he was very close
to a breakthrough.
He said he
needed more time.
He was upset
by our early arrival.
Where in fact, I maintain
that he had already made
that breakthrough
and that he was lying to us.
On what basis?
LA FORGE:
For the last several hours
the Enterprise
has been experiencing
unusual radiation bursts.
We've identified them
as Krieger waves.
Krieger waves?
But that's impossible.
From where?
From right here
inside the holodeck.
PICARD:
We have re-created
your science lab
in every conceivable detail.
Essentially, what was
in the original lab is here.
Including
the Krieger-wave converter
that Dr. Apgar claimed didn't
work, except it does work.
Your field generator
down on the planet surface
has been sending out
harmless energy charges,
which this facsimile has been
converting into Krieger waves.
But the holodeck can't
create anything dangerous.
Well, it didn't.
When you get down to basics,
the converter is nothing more
than a complex series of mirrors
and reflective coils.
The energy from
the field generator
down on the planet
simply reflects off of elements
in the converter,
which turns it into
highly focused Krieger waves.
And those same
waves have been
randomly striking
different areas
of our ship
as we orbit
the planet
and our angle to the
generator changes.
Why would Dr. Apgar lie
about his success?
Computer, run
Manua Program One,
time index 14-3-8.
Manua, someday
I'll be able
to reward you
for all your patience.
I'll get you everything
you ever dreamed of.
I have all the reward I need.
PICARD:
Freeze program.
Computer, run Riker Program Two,
time index 16-1-0.
To your success, Doctor.
And the rewards
that come with it.
PICARD:
Freeze.
I never said that.
Nevertheless,
it seems clear
that your husband
was motivated to
earn the rewards
that pleased you,
Mrs. Apgar.
What's wrong with that?
TROI:
Well, he
wouldn't have
earned great profits from
his dealings with Starfleet.
We were only interested
in a new power source.
But if he could turn this
into a weapon,
it would be worth a lot
to the Romulans, the Ferengi,
and a few others.
Now, Dr. Apgar had been ordering
extra dicosilium for months.
That's a pretty good indication
that he was trying to create
larger reflective coils.
And when the away team
arrived early,
he must have been worried
that Starfleet
was becoming suspicious.
He needed more time
to finish his work.
Apgar said that
in each of the three versions.
No doubt he was afraid
that Commander Riker
might learn the truth
and cut off his support
prematurely.
Discovering
Commander Riker
with his wife
didn't help matters.
I submit he
decided to murder
Commander Riker.
Ridiculous.
Is it?
Computer, run Tayna
Program Four,
time index 18-1-4.
I'll contact the authorities.
No... I'll take
care of that.
PICARD:
Freeze.
Tayna, what exactly
is Apgar doing here?
Activating the generator
on the planet.
Now, why would he do that?
Maybe he was going to work
on the converter.
I don't know.
Maybe he was already
thinking ahead
to his next confrontation
with Commander Riker.
Computer, play
Riker Program Four,
time index 24-1.
What are you going
to put in your
report, Riker?
That there's
no justification
for all the
extra dicosilium
I've requested?
That is why they sent
you early, isn't it?
Doctor...
I can explain
why I needed it.
They have no idea
what my problems are.
There are
explanations for...
I don't need explanations.
PICARD:
Freeze.
To Apgar, this must have
seemed as though
Commander Riker
were confirming
his worst fears,
and I believe it was now
that he finally decided
to kill him.
KRAG:
You forget, Picard.
We know that the energy pulse
which blew up the reactor
originated from
Commander Riker's position
not Dr. Apgar's.
Hmm... We are hypothesizing
that Dr. Apgar energized
the converter
at the moment
of Commander
Riker's beam-out,
hoping to make his
death look like a
transporter accident,
but something
went wrong.
The energy pulse hit
the transporter beam
and reflected back
to the reactor,
which caused
the explosion.
An interesting hypothesis,
but impossible to prove.
LA FORGE:
Not really.
We know that field generator
on the planet
has been repeating a discharge
ever since the explosion.
The intervals are like clockwork
except the explosion occurred
.0014 seconds
after the initial discharge.
Now, the only explanation
for that variance
is the time it would take
the energy pulse to bounce back
from the transporter
beam to the reactor.
We've arranged a demonstration
to illustrate.
Mr. La Forge, I think
it's about time, isn't it?
Computer, load program
La Forge One.
Coordinate auto-engage
time sequence.
The next discharge
from the field generator
is scheduled to
occur in just
a few moments.
Now, we've aligned
the holodeck program
to re-create the final events
as Commander Riker
described them,
only this time, our facsimile
will automatically process
the energy charge
from the planet
and reflect it just
as the original converter did
before the explosion.
If we're correct,
we'll know it instantly.
COMPUTER:
Auto-engage time sequence
synchronized.
Then we have
nothing further
to say to each other.
I'll tell my Captain
to expect your grievance.
Do that.
Riker to Enterprise.
I'm ready to leave now.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by, Commander.
Engaging transport.
Dr. Apgar killed himself
during his attempt
to kill Commander Riker.
Based on this new evidence,
I withdraw my request
for Commander Riker's
extradition.
Commander...
my apologies.
Number One, have we
any further business
in the Tanuga system?
None that I know of.
I'd be more than willing
to put it behind me.
Then perhaps
you would do me the pleasure
of getting this ship underway.
With pleasure, sir.
Ensign Crusher,
set course
for Emila II,
warp three.
Course laid in, sir.
Engage.