All right, try this.
What is it?
Just try it.
You see?
It's an Earth drink.
Prune juice.
Warrior's drink.
You know,
you always drink alone.
It wouldn't hurt you
to seek out a little...
companionship.
I would require a Klingon woman
for... companionship.
Earth females are too fragile.
Not all of them.
There are a few on this ship
that would find you... tame.
( laughing )
Impossible.
You never know
till you try.
Then I will never know.
Coward.
I was merely concerned
for the... safety
of my crewmates.
Drink your prune juice.
RIKER:
Lieutenant Worf,
report to the Bridge.
On my way.
No.
Analysis, Mr. Data.
Sensors are reading gravimetric
fluctuations, Captain.
Most unusual ones.
Unusual in what way?
Specify.
Nothing I have
seen before.
Is it a worm-hole?
Yes and no.
Like a time
displacement,
but it does not have
a discernible event horizon.
Sir, navigational
subsystems are unable
to give coordinates
on the object.
Confirmed.
The phenomenon does not
have a definable center
or outer edge.
Are you saying it is,
and yet it isn't there?
I do not have
sufficient information
to make an analysis as yet,
Commander.
The dynamics
of the radiation patterns...
WORF:
Captain.
Something's happening.
A new change in
sensor readings.
Mr. Data?
Scanning sensors.
Lieutenant, what are
their sensor readings?
Is that an enemy vessel?
I'm getting too much
interference, Captain.
MAN ( over loudspeaker ):
Now hear this:
Fleet formation briefing
in Main War Room at 1500 hours.
Dr. Joshua Kim,
report to Station Ops.
Ensign Thomas, will you report
to Combat Information Center?
Ensign Thomas to CIC.
This isn't right.
It's changed.
It's clearing
now, Captain.
Definitely
a Federation starship.
Accessing registry.
Looks like they had
a rough ride.
NCC-1701... C.
USS... Enterprise.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
PICARD:
Military Log,
Combat-Date 43625.2
While investigating
an unusual radiation anomaly,
the Enterprise has encountered
what could almost be called
a ghost from its own past--
the Enterprise-C,
the immediate predecessor
to this battleship.
Sensors confirm design
and specifications, Captain.
Analysis of hull
and engine materials
conform to engineering patterns
and methods of that time period.
But that cruiser was
destroyed with all hands
over 20 years ago.
Presumed destroyed.
The Enterprise-C
was last seen
near the Klingon
outpost Narendra III
exactly 22 years,
three months, and four days ago.
RIKER:
And now they're here.
PICARD:
Has it been adrift
for all those years?
Or has it traveled through time?
It is a possibility,
Captain.
If that hypothesis
is correct,
the phenomenon
we have just encountered
would be
a temporal rift in space.
A rift?
Possibly the formation
of a Kerr loop
from superstring material.
It would require high-energy
interaction in the vicinity
for such a structure
to be formed.
The rift is certainly
not stable, Captain.
It could collapse at any time.
YAR:
Captain, I'm able to scan
the interior
of the ship now, sir.
Heavy damage
to warp field nacelles
and hull-bearing struts,
internal space frame is...
Life-signs, Captain.
Readings are sporadic.
It looks like they have
massive casualties,
but some are
still alive.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Emergency teams,
stand by transporter rooms.
CRUSHER:
Understood.
Belay that order, Doctor.
Respectfully,
if I may suggest,
regardless
of where they came from,
they are here now,
and they need our help.
Commander, if that ship has
traveled into the future,
we could be dealing
with variables
that will alter
the flow of our history.
( warbling beeps )
Enterprise-C is sending
out a distress call, sir.
Audio only.
Uh-huh.
This is Captain Garrett
of the Starship Enterprise
to any Federation ship.
We have been attacked
by Romulan warships
and require
immediate assistance.
We have lost warp drive,
life-support is failing.
RIKER:
There's no record
of the Romulans
ever assaulting
the Enterprise-C.
Voice message has
ended, Captain.
I'm only receiving their
automated distress signal now.
Open a hailing frequency.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation...
of a Federation starship.
Stand by to receive
emergency teams.
Commander, we will handle this
one step at a time.
Stabilize their
power systems.
Attend to their injured.
And avoid all discussions
of where and when
they are.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant.
Captain, message coming in
from Starfleet
Monitor Stations.
Klingon battle cruisers
headed toward this sector.
Battle Alert, Mr. Crusher.
Condition Yellow.
Aye, sir.
♪♪
Captain Garrett?
Yes.
I'm Commander William Riker.
Our emergency teams
are on board your ship.
Doctor.
The rest of the Bridge crew
is dead.
She has a bad fracture
and serious internal injuries.
I'm going to have to get her
back to the Enterprise.
To where?
We'll explain that later.
You'll explain now,
Commander.
We're from
a Federation starship.
We answered
your distress call.
Your ship is in good hands,
but we need to get you
to our Sick Bay.
Very well.
Crusher to Transporter Room.
Two to beam directly
to Sick Bay.
CREWMAN:
Stand by for transport.
( scanner beeping )
It's pretty bad,
Commander.
Looks like they were
in a hell of a fight.
If you can't stabilize
the life-support,
we're going to have
to evacuate this ship.
No, I think I can do it.
I'll have to get
to Engineering though.
La Forge to Damage
Control Team Alpha.
Meet me on Engineering
level three.
Commander...
( coughing )
( panting and coughing )
Thanks.
Commander William Riker.
Lieutenant Castillo.
Helmsman.
( panting )
DATA:
Away team reporting in, Captain.
On screen.
Go ahead, Commander.
RIKER:
We've stabilized life-support.
Mr. La Forge is working
on restoring
the main power couplings,
but that'll take time.
It's a real mess
down here, sir.
Survivors?
One hundred twenty-five.
Recommendations?
I'd hate to have to scrap her.
Starfleet could certainly
use another ship,
even if she is old.
Agreed, but we can't stay
in this area too long.
You have nine hours.
If you can get her underway
by then,
we'll escort her
to Starbase 105.
If not, we'll evacuate
the survivors
and destroy the ship.
Understood, sir.
Keep me posted.
Picard out.
PICARD:
Guinan?
We need to talk.
Somehow this...
this is all wrong.
This is not the way
it's supposed to be.
But you must have some idea
how things have changed.
I look at things,
I look at people and...
they just don't feel right.
What things, what people?
You.
Your uniform,
the Bridge.
What's the matter
with the Bridge?
It's not right.
It's the same Bridge.
Nothing has changed.
I know that.
I also know it's wrong.
( sighs )
What else?
Families.
There should be children
on this ship.
What?!
Children on the Enterprise?
Guinan, we're at war.
No, we're not.
At least,
we're not supposed to be.
This is not a ship of war.
This is a ship
of peace.
What you're suggesting...
I'm not suggesting.
That ship from the past
is not supposed to be here.
It's got to go back.
MAN:
Get a radiation level.
( patient coughing )
CRUSHER:
Run a full electrolyte report.
MAN:
These organs do
seem to be active.
MAN 2:
Right.
Need a new control specimen.
CRUSHER:
Boost the level
of tricordrazine.
Try to relax.
WOMAN ( over loudspeaker ):
Dr. Salar, report
to Null-G ward, STAT.
Dr. Salar,
report to Null-G ward, STAT.
I'm Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
Rachel Garrett.
How's my ship?
The support systems
are being restored.
We're continuing
repairs.
Where did you come from?
We weren't picking up
any other Federation ships
in this sector.
What's the last thing
you remember?
We were answering
the distress signal.
Distress signal?
You must have heard it.
From the Klingon outpost,
Narendra III.
But you didn't, did you?
This Sick Bay,
I've never seen anything like it
even on a Starbase.
And your uniforms.
What ship is this, Captain?
Please try to be still.
GARRETT:
I must insist.
What ship?
( sighs )
You're aboard the
Enterprise, Captain.
1701-D.
You have come 22 years
into the future.
22 years?
Does my crew know yet?
No.
I must tell them.
I owe them that.
If you wish, I can see
that they're informed.
Is there some reason
they should not be told?
I am concerned that if you
return to your own time
with knowledge of the future...
Return to the battle?
We barely escaped
with our lives.
If we returned,
we'd be destroyed.
Have you any idea
how this happened?
There was a... fierce volley
of photon torpedoes.
We were hit.
A bright light, and then here.
It is possible
that this exchange of fire
was the catalyst
for the formation
of a temporal rift.
History has no record of your
battle with the Romulans.
We were responding
to a distress call
from the Klingon outpost
on Narendra III.
The Romulans were attacking it.
We engaged them,
but there were
four warbirds.
The Narendra III outpost
was destroyed.
It is regrettable
that you did
not succeed.
A Federation starship
rescuing
a Klingon outpost
might have averted
20 years of war.
I still can't quite
make myself believe it.
22 years.
I'm reading 40 percent
on forward shields.
What do you have on aft?
40 percent.
That won't cut it.
Commander,
advise Lieutenant La Forge
that shields are
below minimum.
Acknowledged.
We'll never see our homes again,
our families.
How do you know your
family's not still alive?
You're right, I don't.
But imagine coming home
after 22 years.
Would I even
recognize them?
What are the stats
on the main phaser banks?
Emitters available,
60% forward, 52% aft.
Good. Let's take a look
at the torpedo launchers.
I guess I'm lucky
to be alive at all.
You may not
like the future.
It's been a long war.
The Federation has lost
more than half of Starfleet
to the Klingons.
We were negotiating
a peace treaty when I left.
A lot of changes,
Lieutenant.
A lot of changes.
When we get a break,
maybe you could
fill me in
on some of them.
Photon banks
are depleted.
Auxiliary fusion
generators are down.
There is a high degree
of probability
that the temporal rift
is symmetrical, Captain.
PICARD:
Then what would happen
if the Enterprise-C were
to fly back
through it?
Back, sir?
The Enterprise-C would
emerge in her own time
at almost the same
instant she left.
Right in the middle
of the battle with the Romulans.
Yes, sir.
Is there any possibility
she could survive?
None, sir.
Then sending them back
would be a death sentence.
♪♪
WOMAN ( on loudspeaker ):
Lieutenant Barren...
She was the first
Galaxy-class warship
built by the Federation.
42 decks.
Capable of transporting
over 6,000 troops.
How long have you
been on board?
Four years.
Straight out
of the academy.
I was lucky to get
the Enterprise.
Yeah, me, too.
I mean, my Enterprise.
WOMAN ( on loudspeaker):
Triage Team Two
to Main Shuttle Bay.
Triage Team Two...
( indistinct conversation )
Lieutenant, how's the ship?
We've restored
minimal shields
and the forward
phaser banks.
Still no photon launchers
or warp drive.
Concentrate
on the weapon system.
From what Captain Picard
told me,
the Federation can use
all the help it can get.
YAR:
And soon.
Our sensors have picked
up Klingon warships
in this sector, Captain.
Why wasn't I informed,
Mr. Castillo?
Captain, you shouldn't...
As senior officer,
I want you to be
my liaison
to the Enterprise-D.
Coordinate
with tactical.
YAR:
That's me, Captain.
Where do you think
you're going?
I am resuming
my duties, Doctor.
Captain, you need at least
another 24 hours.
Nonsense, doctors always
overprotect their patients.
And Captains always push
themselves too hard.
Doctor, my ship
and my crew need me now.
24 hours might as well
be 24 years.
( door opens )
I need more.
There is no more.
I wish there were.
I wish I could prove it,
but I can't.
Then I can't
ask them to go back.
You've got to.
Guinan, they will die
moments after they return.
How can I ask them
to sacrifice themselves
based solely on your intuition?
I don't know.
But I do know
that this is a mistake.
Every fiber in my being says
this is a mistake.
I can't explain it to myself,
so I can't explain it to you.
I only know that I'm right.
Who is to say
that this history
is any less proper
than the other?
I suppose I am.
Not good enough, damn it,
not good enough!
I will not ask
them to die!
40 billion people
have already died.
This war is not supposed
to be happening.
You've got to send those people
back to correct this.
And what is to guarantee that if
they go back, they will succeed?
Every instinct is telling me
this is wrong,
it is dangerous,
it is futile!
We've known each other
a long time.
You have never known me
to impose myself on anyone
or take a stance
based on trivial
or whimsical perceptions.
This timeline must not
be allowed to continue.
Now, I've told you
what you must do.
You have only your trust in me
to help you decide to do it.
( door closes )
I mean, deflector
shield technology
has advanced considerably
during the war.
Our heat-dissipation
rates are probably double
those of the Enterprise-C.
Which means we can hang in
a firefight a lot longer.
Guinan?
Have you ordered yet, Tasha?
No, not yet.
Is anything wrong?
Not a thing.
What can I get for you?
Just a couple of T-K-Ls.
We're in a hurry.
Oh, this is
Lieutenant Castillo.
Mm.
First time for everything.
First time?
It's just that I've never seen
anything bother her before.
What's a T-K-L?
Standard rations.
Food replicators
are on minimum power
so everything else is diverted
to the defensive systems.
So where was I?
You've told me more
about tactical in an hour
than I learned in my last year
at the academy.
You're going to
need it, Lieutenant.
Hey...
I've known you
a whole day now, Lieutenant.
I won't salute if you won't.
What did she
call you-- Tasha?
Yeah.
Most everyone
calls me Castillo.
My mother calls me Richard.
Okay, Castillo.
No, I think maybe
I'd like it better
if you called me Richard.
Richard.
PICARD:
This is the Captain.
Senior officers will report
to my ready room
immediately.
So much for lunch.
Captain, are you suggesting
that we let them return
and attempt to complete
their mission?
I am, Doctor.
Based on Guinan's
intuition?
That won't accomplish
anything, sir.
There's no way they can save
Narendra III.
Captain Garrett said there
were four Romulan warbirds.
The Enterprise-C would be
outmanned and outgunned.
Unless we were
to re-arm them
with modern...
PICARD:
We can't do that.
If we send that ship back
with new technology,
we'll be altering the past.
RIKER:
But that's what you're
talking about anyway,
isn't it-- altering the past?
We're talking
about restoring the past.
But how could Guinan know
that history's been altered
if she's been altered
along with the rest of us?
Perhaps her species
has a perception
that goes beyond
linear time.
PICARD:
There are many things
about her species
we can't easily explain.
Yet, it is very possible
that she is correct.
A ship from the past
has traveled through time.
How can we know
what effect those events
will have on the present?
Indeed, we shall never
know for certain
if Guinan is correct,
but I have decided the
consequences of that possibility
are too grave to ignore.
Dismissed.
RIKER:
Sir, if you'd
like my opinion...
I think I'm aware
of your opinion, Commander.
This is a briefing.
I'm not seeking your consent.
With all due respect, sir
you'd be asking 125 people
to die a meaningless death.
DATA:
Not necessarily
meaningless, Commander.
The Klingons regard honor
above all else.
If the crew
of the Enterprise-C had died
fighting for the survival
of a Klingon outpost,
it would be considered
a meaningful act of honor
by the Klingon Empire.
Even their deaths could have
prevented this war.
If the Enterprise-C
returns to the battle
and its mission is a success,
history will be
irrevocably changed.
This timeline will
cease to exist,
and a new future will
have been created.
I've considered
the alternatives.
I'll go with Guinan's
recommendation.
Dismissed.
If she's right,
we may not even be
in an alternate timeline.
Who knows if we're
even dead or alive?
Engineering.
Is Engineering your
destination as well?
What?
Oh, deck six.
Sorry.
( lift whirring )
If I interpret your facial
expressions correctly,
you are preoccupied
with something unpleasant.
No, I...
I was just thinking...
about a lot of things.
( sighs )
I've-I've been working
with one of the officers
on the Enterprise-C.
You know, he's-he's nice.
I like him.
I'm worried about what's
going to happen to him.
We may never know
what happens.
If they succeed,
we will not even realize
that these events occurred.
Shields are
up to 72%.
That's better.
Good.
GARRETT:
Do you believe this Guinan?
I discovered long ago
that she has
a special wisdom.
I've learned to trust it.
I could arrange for you
to speak with her, if you wish.
Captain, I would be lying
to you if I told you
there was a chance in hell
of coming out of this alive.
Why doesn't your ship
come back with us?
The Romulans would be
no match for your weaponry.
I can't do that.
No, I suppose not.
You don't belong in our time
any more than we belong
in yours.
To be honest
with you, Picard...
a significant number
of my crew members
have expressed
the desire to return,
even knowing the odds.
Some, because they can't bear to
live without their loved ones...
some, because
they don't like the idea
of slipping out
in the middle of a fight.
But I have told them
that, in the here and now,
the Federation needs another
ship against the Klingons...
and we'd better get used
to being in the here and now.
But, if you go back, it could be
a great deal more helpful.
( crew members
conversing quietly )
The war is going very badly
for the Federation.
Far worse than
is generally known.
Starfleet Command believes
that defeat is inevitable.
Within six months,
we may have no choice
but to surrender.
And you're saying
that all this
may be a result
of our arrival here?
One more ship will make no
difference in the here and now,
but, 22 years ago,
one ship could have
stopped this war
before it started.
Mr. Castillo.
CASTILLO:
Yes, Captain.
Inform the crew
we're going back.
Yes, Captain.
The Romulans will
get a good fight.
We'll make it one
for the history books.
I know you will, Captain.
Lieutenant Yar.
Permission to remain
a moment, sir.
Granted.
GARRETT:
Transporter room,
Captain Picard is ready
to return to his ship.
CREWMAN:
Aye, Captain.
I just wanted
to say good luck.
I'll try to put some
of your tactical briefing
to good use
when we get back.
Your ship has much
more maneuverability
than the Romulan
counterparts
of that era.
Actually, if you
could just isolate...
You'll do fine.
If you get back to Earth
and you see a man...
say, in his late 50s,
taking a hard, long look
across a crowded room...
Hey, you never know.
Good-bye, Lieutenant.
(explosion)
Whoa!
GARRETT:
Red Alert.
Full power to shields.
Shields are up.
Functioning.
Initiating evasive maneuvers,
Gamma sequence.
Ready phasers.
Enterprise-D, has your Captain
returned safely?
RIKER:
Acknowledged.
Captain Picard is safely aboard.
Fire phasers.
DATA:
Firing phasers.
( sound of phaser blips )
Report.
One Klingon bird-of-prey
off the starboard bow.
Firing phasers.
Load torpedo bays.
( shouts )
( alarm blaring )
The Klingon vessel
has re-cloaked, sir.
I have no readings.
Captain Garrett, damage report.
PICARD:
Captain Garrett?!
This is Lieutenant Yar, sir.
Captain Garrett is dead.
I'm prepared to lead
the Enterprise back myself,
Captain Picard.
Sir, Lieutenant Castillo
is the last surviving
senior officer.
He will have limited support
from ops, no tactical,
reduced staff
in Engineering...
I have good people
willing to do their best.
Certainly, history never
meant for this ship
to go into battle
without her Captain.
I can't speak to
that point, sir,
but I can get us back
to where we're supposed to be.
I believe that's what Captain
Garrett would want me to do.
DATA: Commander Data
to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
Sir, sensors are showing
additional instability
in the time rift,
possibly the result
of the battle with the Klingons.
Any signs of other
Klingon vessels?
No, sir.
Our coordinates
have been transmitted
to the Klingon
Command, sir.
We mustn't remain here.
CASTILLO:
Sir, it is my intention
to return,
unless you order me not to.
How soon can your ship
be ready?
We sustained moderate damage
in the attack.
I think we can
get underway in a few hours.
Make it so.
We'll give you cover.
MAN:
...meet him down in the docking
area on the double.
One to beam
to the Enterprise-C.
We keep saying good-bye,
don't we?
I wish we had more time.
More time?
I think we have all the time
we can handle as it is.
Lieutenant.
( door opens and closes )
Can I get you something, Tasha?
Guinan, I have
to know something.
What happens to me
in the other timeline?
I don't have alternate
biographies of the crew.
As I said to the Captain,
it's just a feeling.
But there's something more
when you look at me,
isn't there?
I can see it in
your eyes, Guinan.
We've known each
other too long.
We weren't meant to know
each other at all.
At least, that's what I sense
when I look at you.
Tasha, you're not supposed
to be here.
Where am I supposed to be?
Dead.
Do you know how?
No.
But I do know
it was an empty death--
a death without purpose.
( door chime )
PICARD:
Come.
Yes, Lieutenant?
Captain, I request a transfer
to the Enterprise-C.
For what reason?
They need someone
at tactical.
We need you here.
I'm not supposed
to be here, sir.
Sit down, Lieutenant.
What did she say to you?
I don't belong here, sir.
I'm, I'm...
supposed to be dead.
She felt it necessary
to reveal that to you?
I felt it was necessary.
I see.
You realize
that it is very possible
the Enterprise-C will fail.
We will continue
in this timeline.
In which case,
your life, hopefully,
will continue for a long while.
I know how important it is
that they don't fail, Captain.
That's why I'm requesting
this transfer.
You don't belong
on that ship, Lieutenant.
No, Captain Garrett
belongs on that ship,
but she's dead.
And I think there's a certain
logic in this request.
There's no logic
in this at all!
Whether they succeed or not...
...the Enterprise-C
will be destroyed.
But, Captain,
at least with someone
at tactical,
they will have a chance
to defend themselves well.
It may be a matter
of seconds or minutes,
but those could be the minutes
that change history.
Guinan says
I died a senseless death
in the other timeline.
I didn't like the sound
of that, Captain.
I've always known the risks
that come
with a Starfleet uniform.
If I'm to die in one...
I'd like my death
to count for something.
Lieutenant...
Permission granted.
Thank you, sir.
I'm showing phaser banks
up to 70% efficiency.
We've got an hour left.
Let's see if we can
get them up to 90.
MAN:
Aye, sir.
Parker, you've got Ops.
Fredericks,
take the conn.
I'll handle tactical.
Lieutenant Tasha Yar
reporting for duty, sir.
You're not
part of my crew.
I am now.
Captain Picard approved
my request for transfer.
This isn't a joke, Tasha.
We're going back into the rift,
into battle.
We're not coming back.
I know the mission.
These are my orders,
Lieutenant.
But I don't want you here.
You need me here.
Show me someone
in your crew
who can do the job
better than I can.
Welcome aboard.
Take your station, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Military Log, supplemental.
Lieutenant Tasha Yar
has transferred
to the Enterprise-C,
where she has taken over
tactical duties.
Meanwhile,
our long-range scanners
have picked up
Klingon battle cruisers
on an intercept course.
Number and type of
ships, Mr. Crusher?
Three K'vort-class
battle cruisers, sir.
They're not even troubling
to cloak themselves.
They shouldn't be so confident
after the pasting
we gave them on Archer IV.
( bosun's whistle blows )
Attention, all hands.
As you know, we could outrun
the Klingon vessels,
but we must protect
the Enterprise-C
until she enters
the temporal rift,
and we must succeed.
Let's make sure
that history never forgets
the name... Enterprise.
Picard out.
♪♪
PICARD:
Mr. Data?
Shields are holding, sir.
Hold fire.
Mr. Crusher, come about
to course 1-4-8-0-0-3.
Aye, sir.
Photon torpedoes ready.
Dispersal pattern: Sierra.
And fire.
One enemy target hit, sir.
Moderate damage to
their forward shields.
( explosion )
Our shields are
still holding.
Minor damage
to secondary hull.
Course 148...
Correction.
Course 170,
mark 014.
Sir, one of the ships
is breaking off
and going toward
the Enterprise-C.
Mr. Crusher, keep us within 200
kilometers of the Enterprise-C.
Coming to 217 mark 115.
Increasing
to two-thirds impulse.
Damage control
teams, deck 14.
Engineering to Bridge, starboard
power coupling is down.
Containment field
generator three is damaged.
Attempting to bypass.
If we lose
antimatter
containment...
Acknowledged, La Forge.
Sir, the Klingons
are flanking us,
attempting to draw us away
from the Enterprise-C.
Hold course,
Mr. Crusher.
Continual fire, all phasers.
One enemy target destroyed, sir.
( yells )
Damage report.
Heavy casualties
in the secondary hull.
Navigational sensor array
inoperative.
( alarm blaring )
( overlapping shouting )
Antimatter containment fields
are failing.
If I can't stabilize them,
I'll have to dump
the reactor core or she'll blow!
Shields buckling, Captain.
They will not...
La Forge to Bridge.
I can't hold the antimatter
containment fields.
Initiating emergency shutdown.
( alarm sounding )
Coolant leak.
Bridge, we've got
a coolant leak
in the engine core,
I can't shut it down.
I estimate two minutes
to a warp core breach!
Come on, get out!
Go, go, go, go, go!
How long before
the Enterprise-C
enters the rift?
52 seconds, sir.
All remaining power
to the defense systems.
Power couplings severed
in forward phaser banks.
Attempting
to bypass.
Controls not responding.
( Riker screams )
KLINGON:
Federation Ship Enterprise,
surrender and prepare
to be boarded.
That will be the day.
( alarm whooping )
( explosion )
Report, Lieutenant.
Readings fluctuated
momentarily.
It appeared to be a ship,
but then it vanished.
The phenomenon is closing in
on itself, Captain.
Very well.
Prepare a Class-1 sensor probe.
We'll leave it behind
to monitor the final closure.
Mr. Crusher, lay in a course
for Archer IV.
Captain, this is Guinan.
Is everything all right
up there?
Guinan?
Yes, everything's fine.
Is something wrong?
No... no, everything's fine.
Sorry to bother you.
Geordi, tell me about...
Tasha Yar.
♪♪