Captain's Log,
Stardate 43657.0.
While Commander Riker is away
on personal leave
the Enterprise has traveled
to Sector 396
to begin charting
the Salebi Asteroid Belt.
He sent for you, too?
Yes.
He was very mysterious.
Do you have any idea
what this is about?
Something happened at that
cybernetics conference.
Since he's come back,
he's spent
every off-duty minute
in that lab.
It's not like Data
to be so secretive.
And cautious.
He's kept that lab
locked every minute.
Now, how would
you know that?
Uh-huh.
DATA:
Oh, you are early.
One moment, please.
DATA:
You may enter now.
Come on, Data.
What is this?
Yeah, Data,
what's going on?
I have invited you here
to meet someone.
DATA:
This is Lal.
Lal...
Say hello
to Counselor Deanna Troi.
Hello, Counselor Deanna Troi.
How do you do, Lal?
I am functioning
within normal parameters.
Lal...
this is Geordi La Forge.
Purpose for exterior drapings,
Father?
It is an accepted
custom
that we wear clothing.
Data, it called you "Father."
Yes, Wesley, Lal is my child.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I have just been advised
of a highly unusual project
undertaken by Commander Data.
Lal has a positronic brain,
one very similar to my own.
I began programming it
at the cybernetics conference.
LA FORGE:
But nobody's ever been
able to do that, Data.
At least, not since
you were programmed.
DATA:
True, but there was
a new sub-micron
matrix-transfer technology
introduced
at the conference
which I discovered
could be used
to lay down complex
neural net pathways.
So, you did a transfer
from your brain
into Lal's?
Exactly, Wesley.
I realized
for the first time
that it was possible
to continue Dr. Soong's work.
My initial transfers
produced very
encouraging results.
So I brought Lal's
brain back with me.
PICARD:
Data...
I would like
to have been consulted.
I have not observed
anyone else on board
consulting you about their
procreation, Captain.
( sighs deeply )
Why didn't you give it
a more human look, Data?
I have decided
to allow my child
to choose its own
sex and appearance.
Commander Data,
at your convenience
I would like to talk with you
in my ready room.
Counselor.
I insist we do
whatever we can
to discourage
the perception
of this new android
as a child.
It is not a child.
It is an invention, albeit
an extraordinary one.
Why should biology
rather than technology
determine whether
it's a child?
Data has created
an offspring--
a new life out
of his own being.
To me, that
suggests a child.
If he wishes
to call Lal his child
then who are we to argue?
Well, if he must, but
I fail to understand
how a five-foot android
with heuristic
learning systems
and the strength of ten men
can be called a child.
You've never been a parent.
What you have done
will have serious
ramifications.
I am truly dismayed
that you told no one
of what you were doing.
I am sorry, Captain.
I did not anticipate
your objections.
Do you wish me
to deactivate Lal?
It's a life, Data!
It can't be activated
and deactivated simply.
This is a most...
stupendous undertaking.
Have you any idea
what will happen
when Starfleet
learns about this?
I have followed all
of Starfleet's regulations
to the best of my ability.
I expected
they would be pleased.
( sighs deeply )
Well... you have taken on
quite a responsibility, Data.
To prepare, I have scanned
all available literature
on parenting.
There seems to be
much confusion on this issue.
One traditional doctrine
insists "spare the rod
and spoil the child,"
suggesting a punitive approach,
while another,
more liberal attitude
would allow the child
enormous freedom.
Data...
And what Klingons
do to their children...
Data, I am not talking
about parenting!
I am talking about the
extraordinary consequences
of creating a new life!
Does that not describe
becoming a parent, sir?
Data, you are seeking
to achieve
what only your own creator
has been able to achieve--
to make another functioning
sentient android--
to make another Data.
That is why I must
attempt this, sir.
I have observed
that in most species
there is a primal instinct
to perpetuate themselves.
Until now, I have been
the last of my kind.
If I were to be damaged
or destroyed
I would be lost forever.
But if I am successful
with the creation of Lal
my continuance is assured.
I understand the risks, sir,
and I am prepared
to accept the responsibility.
( woman chuckling )
Gender female.
That's right,
just like me.
Gender male.
Correct.
And I am gender... neuter.
Inadequate.
That is why you must
choose a gender, Lal,
to complete your appearance.
What are criteria?
Access your data bank
on sexuality, level two.
That will define
the parameters.
Whatever you decide
will be yours for
your lifetime.
It's a decision that
will affect how people
interrelate with you.
I choose your sex
and appearance.
No, Lal.
That would be confusing.
We are taking you
to the holodeck
to show you several
thousand composites
I have programmed.
You may choose from them.
Several thousand?
This is a big decision.
DATA:
Counselor?
Lal has narrowed
the choices to four.
Would you like to see?
Yes.
Yes, of course, Data.
Computer, Lal-- gender
sequence finalists, begin.
An Andorian female.
Interesting.
You'll be the only one
on board the Enterprise, Lal.
Hmm. That could make
socialization
more difficult.
A human male.
Very attractive.
There's no problem
with socialization here.
A human female.
I like her.
A Klingon male.
A friend for Worf.
They're all very interesting.
Do you have a favorite?
Yes, I have chosen.
I have completed assembly
of the replicated anatomy.
I was able to provide Lal
with more realistic skin
and eye color than my own.
Congratulations, Data.
It's a girl.
This is home, Lal.
Home.
Place of residence.
Social unit formed by
a family living together.
Yes.
We are a family, Lal.
Chair.
To sit in.
Sit.
Good.
Painting.
Colors produced
on a surface by
applying a pigment.
Yes.
I will teach you to recognize
the artistry in paintings.
Soft.
Yes, very good, Lal.
You have correctly processed
the sense of touch.
There are many
fascinating experiences
I wish to share with you.
Painting.
No.
That is a flower, Lal.
Inhale.
( sniffs )
Smell!
Yes.
Show me more, Father.
DATA:
Second Officer,
Science Log, supplemental.
Training in social skills
at the most elementary level
has begun.
Lal is progressing very slowly
but is not deterred
by early setbacks.
While motor coordination
has improved 12 percent,
reflexes still need
to develop.
Visual comprehension is
especially difficult for Lal.
Translating her vast data banks
into recognizable applications
may improve
with additional transfers.
She is also learning
to supplement
her innate android behavior
with simulated human responses.
And it is interesting to note
that as I observe Lal
learning about her world,
I share in her experience,
almost as though
I am learning things
over again.
The transfer itself
is fairly simple.
Each neural pathway
in my brain
is duplicated
precisely in hers.
Theoretically,
the duplicate brains
should be able to store and
process the same information,
but until all of the transfers
are complete
we will not know for certain.
What does Lal do
when you're on duty?
She studies in our quarters.
She requires
very little supervision.
Lal is quite self-sufficient.
Have you considered
sending her to school?
She already has access
to the sum of human knowledge--
from me.
Data, she could learn
a lot by being with
children her own age.
She is only two weeks old.
Okay, close to her own age.
CRUSHER: Dr. Crusher
to Ensign Crusher.
Aren't you supposed to be
getting a haircut, Wesley?
I'm on my way.
Parents...
Nothing personal.
Lal, the third cross-link
transfer series is complete.
Father, what is my purpose?
Purpose?
My function.
My reason for being.
That is a complex
question, Lal.
I can only begin
to answer
by telling you
that our function
is to contribute
in a positive way
to the world in which we live.
Why am I me, instead
of someone else?
Because you are my child.
Where did I come from?
These questions...
These questions suggest
that we have made
a successful transfer
of the heuristic
associative pathways.
You will now begin
to process information
on logic, aesthetics,
metaphysics and epistemology.
You are truly
becoming sentient, Lal.
How?
By developing the awareness
to question and examine
your perceptions.
Why do we have two hands?
Why not three or four?
Why is the sky black?
Why do...?
( click )
Tomorrow will be your
first day of school, Lal.
I assure you, Admiral,
there is no better guide
into this life for Lal
than Data.
He's doing an excellent job.
We all have enormous admiration
for what Commander Data
has already achieved
but we have superior facilities
and personnel here at Galor IV.
A starship is hardly
the proper setting for...
This starship's mission is
to seek out new life
and that is exactly
what Commander Data is doing,
under my guidance.
We all want what's best
for the new android.
As do I.
( sighs )
I would be willing to consider
releasing Lal and Data to you
so that he may continue
his work with her.
His presence
would undoubtedly retard
the new android's progress.
Admiral, to you,
Lal is a new android.
But, to Data...
she's his child.
His child?
Yes, Admiral--
it may not be easy
for you and I
to see her that way
but he does,
and I respect that.
They will remain here for now.
Starfleet's policy on research
is clear.
You're making your stand
on very uncertain ground.
I do hope it doesn't fall
out from under you.
Haftel out.
She achieved
a very high score
on a test
of academic achievement.
A perfect score.
Yes, which is why we started her
out with the older children,
but Lal couldn't
understand the nuances
of how they related
to each other.
I see.
We decided
the best thing to do
would be to put her
with younger children.
That would seem
to be reasonable.
It isn't working out that way.
The children
are afraid of her.
Father, what is the significance
of laughter?
It is a human
physiological
response to humor.
Then, judging
from their laughter,
the children at school
found my remarks humorous.
So without understanding humor,
I have somehow mastered it.
Deck 15.
Lal.
Yes, Father?
The children were not
laughing with you.
They were laughing at you.
Explain.
One is meant kindly,
the other is not.
Why would they wish
to be unkind?
Because you are different.
Differences
sometimes scare people.
I have learned
that some of them
use humor to hide their fear.
I do not wish to be different.
Doctor?
I require your advice
as a successful parent.
Uh! W-Well, thank you, Data.
I'd like to think I was.
Well, please sit down.
How's Lal?
Lal is realizing
she is not the same
as other children.
Is it lonely for her?
She does
not feel
the emotion of loneliness,
but she can observe how isolated
she is from the others.
She wishes to be more like them.
I do not know
how to help her.
Lal is passing into sentience.
It is perhaps the most difficult
stage of her development.
When... when Wesley
was growing up
he was an extraordinarily
bright boy,
but he had a hard time
making friends.
I think the other children
were a little
intimidated by him.
That is precisely what
happened to Lal in school.
How did you help him?
Well... first, I went back
to my own childhood
and remembered
how painful it was for me
because... I remember a time
when I wasn't very popular,
either.
And when I told that to Wesley
it made him feel
a little better.
He knew I understood
what he was going through.
I have not told Lal
how difficult it was for me
to assimilate.
I did not wish
to discourage her.
Perhaps that was an error
in judgment.
You didn't have anyone
with experience
to help you through sentience.
She, at least, has you.
Just help her realize
she's not alone
and... be there to nurture her
when she needs love
and attention.
I can give her attention,
Doctor,
but I am incapable
of giving her love.
Now, why do I find that
so hard to believe?
( rapid beeping )
WORF:
Captain, incoming signal.
Starfleet priority one.
Admiral Haftel.
On my monitor, Lieutenant.
Admiral.
HAFTEL:
Captain Picard, I hope
I didn't disturb you.
Not at all.
I have discussed my concerns
with Starfleet Command.
You are to hold your position
until I join you.
And I shall personally review
the android's development.
Understood.
I should advise you, Captain,
that if I'm not satisfied
with what I see,
I am empowered to take
the android back with me.
Haftel out.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are holding position
pending the arrival
of Admiral Haftel
from Starfleet Research.
Commander Data is completing
his final neural transfers
to the android
he has named "Lal,"
which, I have learned,
in the language Hindi
means "beloved."
That looks very good.
Thanks, Guinan.
Hello, Data.
Guinan.
Lal, how are you?
I am functioning
within normal...
I am fine, thank you.
Good.
Guinan, Lal needs
to observe human behavior.
Well, she's in
the right place for it.
And, for this opportunity
she is willing
to provide services
to assist you.
Ah.
Father says
I would learn
a great deal
from working
with someone
as old as you.
You're hired.
The most important part about
working someplace like this
is the art of listening.
I have some expertise,
so I shall teach you.
That would be
most beneficial.
I've been programmed
with a listing of 1,412
known beverages.
What did you say?
I've been programmed
with a listing of 1,400--
"I've"?
You have used
a verbal contraction.
You said "I've"
instead of "I have."
It is a skill my program
has never mastered.
Then I will desist.
No.
You have exceeded my abilities.
I do not object, but...
I do not understand
how this has occurred.
PICARD: Picard
to Commander Data.
Please report to my ready room.
Aye, sir.
I am certain the Admiral
is anxious to meet Lal.
I have been sending him
regular status reports
on her development.
His visit is not just an
inspection of Lal's progress.
He has expressed
a concern
for her environment.
Her environment, sir?
He believes the Daystrom Annex
on Galor IV
would be more suitable.
Then he wishes to relocate us.
Not you, Data.
Just her.
I would not be
in favor of that, sir.
There are many things that she
can learn only from me--
my lifetime of experiences,
the mistakes I have made
and what I have learned
from them...
WORF:
Captain, Commander Riker's
shuttle has just returned.
Acknowledged,
Lieutenant.
Will you advise
Commander Riker
I will meet with
him in one hour.
Picard out.
The Admiral is
taking the position
that Lal's development
should be overseen
by the most
experienced
personnel.
Then he is questioning
my ability as a parent.
In a manner of speaking.
Does the Admiral have children?
Yes, I believe he does, Data.
Why?
I am forced to wonder
how much experience
he had as a parent
when his first child was born.
You see?
What are they doing?
It's called flirting.
They seem to be communicating
telepathically.
They're both thinking
the same thing
if that's what you mean.
Guinan, is the joining of hands
a symbolic act for humans?
It shows affection.
Humans like to
touch each other.
They start with the
hands and go from there.
He's biting that female!
No, he's not biting her.
They're pressing lips.
It's called kissing.
Why are they leaving?
Lal, there are some things
your father's just going
to have to explain to you
when he thinks
you're ready.
You're new around
here, aren't you?
Yes.
Lal? Lal!
Put him down.
DATA:
Commander?
What are your intentions
toward my daughter?
Your daughter?
Nice to meet you.
I watch them and I can do
the things they do,
but I will never
feel the emotions.
I'll never know love.
It is a limitation
we must learn to accept, Lal.
Then why do you still try
to emulate humans?
What purpose does it serve
except to remind you
that you are incomplete?
I have asked myself
that many times
as I have struggled
to be more human.
Until I realized it
is the struggle itself
that is most important.
We must strive to be
more than we are, Lal.
It does not matter
that we will never reach
our ultimate goal.
The effort yields
its own rewards.
You are wise, Father.
It is the difference between
knowledge and experience.
I learned today that humans
like to hold hands.
It is a symbolic gesture
of affection.
No objective viewpoint
could see it any other way.
Forgive me, Admiral, I
thought you were sent here
to form an opinion,
not to justify one.
Captain, let's not make this
any more difficult
than it needs to be, hmm?
I see no need
for it to be difficult at all.
I understand your concerns.
What I'm asking for
is time, patience.
If you have
an open mind
I'm sure you
will see
that it is imperative that Data
and Lal be kept together
during the formative stages
of her development.
After that, I have no doubt
Commander Data will be delighted
to deliver her
to Starfleet Research.
That's not satisfactory.
If mistakes are made,
the damage that's done
might be irreparable.
I'm convinced the damage
will be irreparable
if they're separated.
Captain, are we talking
about breaking up a family?
Isn't that rather a sentimental
attitude about androids?
They're living, sentient beings.
Their rights and privileges in
our society have been defined.
I helped define them.
Yes, Captain, and I am
more than willing
to acknowledge that.
What you must acknowledge
is that Lal may be
a technological step forward
in the development
of artificial intelligence.
A most significant step.
Yes, and work like this
demands to be done
with controlled procedures.
Which Commander Data
is following.
In effective isolation,
and that is what Starfleet
Research finds unacceptable.
So Lal now possesses
the sum of my programming.
Her neural nets
are laid down
identically to yours?
There do seem to be some
variations on the quantum level.
She can use contractions.
I cannot.
An aberration.
What have you done about this?
I have maintained records
on positronic matrix activity,
behavioral norms,
and all verbal patterns.
I have seen no other evidence
of aberrations.
It would seem you have actually
improved upon yourself, Data.
Is that not the goal
of every parent, sir?
But, as a good father,
don't you think
it would be better
especially in the light
of this new aberration
if Lal were close
to people trained
in diagnostic
and evaluative
procedures?
I am programmed with the
procedures you mentioned, sir,
and in any meaningful
evaluation of Lal
you would require a model
for a basis of comparison.
I am the only model available,
Admiral.
You haven't mastered
human cultural
and behavioral norms
yourself yet, have you?
No, sir.
Where is Lal now?
This is your idea of
appropriate guidance?
It is an opportunity for her
to observe human behavior,
and more importantly, for her
to interact with her crewmates.
Thank you.
She is capable of running
over 60 trillion calculations
a second,
and you have her working
as a cocktail waitress.
Admiral, she is under
the strict guidance of a woman
in whom I have absolute trust.
Ten-Forward is the center
of the ship's social activity.
Everyone on board comes here.
I'm not convinced the sort
of behavior she observes here
will be a positive influence.
Well, most people
when they come in here
behave themselves,
and when they don't
I ask them to leave.
Admiral Haftel, Guinan.
She runs Ten-Forward.
How is Lal doing?
Oh, she spills a few
drinks every now and then,
but she's learning.
( woman laughing )
No, I think I've had
enough, thank you.
Excuse me.
I want that android out of here.
Now, Admiral, you've
been in one or two bars
in your time.
Have her report to me
immediately for an interview.
Well, Lal, I've been
looking forward to meeting you.
Why?
You're very important to us
at Starfleet Research.
We have quite a facility
at Galor IV.
I want to show it to you.
In fact, the Admiral
is suggesting
you be moved to Galor IV, Lal.
Have I done
something wrong?
Oh, no, of course not.
We just want to broaden
your experience.
There's only so much
you can learn on a starship.
I'm sure you'll agree to that.
Yes, I'll agree.
Good.
Thus, the natural conclusion
would be
when I have learned all there is
to learn aboard the starship
I would relocate to Galor IV.
That is not
the natural conclusion here.
I believe it is.
You see, Lal, the
Admiral is concerned
that you need
more... guidance
than your father
can provide here
on the Enterprise.
Yes, don't misunderstand me.
I have great respect
for your father.
You do not speak
with respect.
She seems very
adversarial.
I'm merely stating a fact,
Admiral.
I don't think your father has
taught you selective judgment
in the verbalization
of your own thoughts.
Now, that is a skill
we will help you develop.
My father is
already helping me, sir.
The question is,
has he helped you enough?
Are you asking me, sir?
No, I didn't mean to ask...
Why don't we, Admiral?
In all these discussions,
no one has ever mentioned
her wishes.
She's a free, sentient being.
PICARD:
What are your
wishes, Lal?
I wish to remain here,
Captain Picard.
Thank you, Lal.
You're excused.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Lal.
How are you?
Troi...
Admiral... Admiral...
An admiral from Starfleet
has come to take me away, Troi.
I am scared.
You are scared,
aren't you?
I feel it.
How is this possible?
I don't know.
This is what it
means to feel.
This is what it means...
"feel."
You have Lal off to a wonderful
start in life, Commander.
And that's what being a parent
is all about.
However, I have finally decided
that I must ask you
to release her to me.
May I ask why, sir?
All other arguments aside,
there's one
that is irrefutable.
There are only two Soong-type
androids in existence.
It would be very dangerous
to have you both
in the same place,
especially aboard a starship.
One lucky shot by a Romulan,
we'd lose you both.
Admiral, that is
a fine argument, but...
it doesn't change my feeling
that the proper place
for Lal to develop
is by Data's side.
You're not a parent, Captain.
I am.
I have learned, with difficulty,
that there comes a time when...
There comes a time
when all parents
must give up
their children
for their own good.
But this is not the time.
Damn it, even I can see the...
the umbilical cord
is virtually uncut.
The child...
The child depends on him.
Mr. Data, it would
be better for Lal
if she left knowing that
you had voluntarily decided
that this was the best
course of action.
Admiral, when I
created Lal,
it was in the hope that someday
she would choose
to enter the academy
and become a member
of Starfleet.
I wanted to give something back
in return for all
that Starfleet has given me.
I still do.
But Lal is my child.
You ask that I volunteer
to give her up.
I cannot.
It would violate
every lesson
I have learned
about human parenting.
I have brought a new life
into this world.
And it is my duty,
not Starfleet's
to guide her through these
difficult steps to maturity,
to support her as she learns,
to prepare her to be a
contributing member of society.
No one can relieve me
from that obligation,
and I cannot ignore it.
I am...
her father.
Then I regret
that I must order you
to transport Lal aboard my ship.
Belay that order,
Mr. Data.
I beg your pardon.
I will take this
to Starfleet myself.
I am Starfleet, Captain.
Proceed, Commander.
Hold your ground, Mr. Data.
Captain, you are
jeopardizing
your command and your career.
There are times, sir,
when men of good conscience
cannot blindly follow orders.
You acknowledge their sentience
but you ignore their personal
liberties and freedom.
( sighs )
Order a man to hand his child
over to the state?
Not while I am his Captain.
If you wish,
you can accompany us
to Starfleet, where we shall...
TROI:
Troi to Commander Data.
Report to your lab at once.
Acknowledged, Counselor.
He's on his way.
Is there a problem?
Yes, Captain, something
is terribly wrong with Lal.
TROI:
It lasted
barely a moment.
She experienced
fear and confusion
and then, for no
apparent reason
she walked out
of my quarters.
She didn't say
another word.
She just started
walking here and
each step became
more and more
difficult.
Lal is programmed
to return to the lab
in the event of a malfunction.
Father?
Yes, Lal, I am here.
A malfunction...
emotional awareness.
It appears to be a symptom
of cascade failure.
It would require initialization
of the base matrix
without wiping out
higher functions.
I agree.
May I assist?
Thank you, Admiral.
If you'll excuse us,
Commander Data and I
have much to do.
( door opens and closes )
( instrument whirring )
( click )
( beeping )
( door opens )
She...
she won't survive much longer.
There was nothing
anyone could have done.
We'd repolarize one pathway,
and another would collapse.
And then another.
His hands... were moving faster
than I could see,
trying to stay ahead
of each breakdown.
He refused to give up.
He was remarkable.
It just... wasn't meant to be.
Lal, I am unable to correct
the system failure.
I know.
We must say good-bye now.
I feel...
What do you feel, Lal?
I love you, Father.
I wish I could
feel it with you.
I will feel it
for both of us.
Thank you for my life.
Flirting.
Laughter.
Painting, family.
Female.
Human...
Lal suffered complete neural
system failure at 1300 hours.
I have deactivated the unit.
The crew is saddened
by your loss, Mr. Data.
I thank you for your sympathy,
but... she is here.
Her presence so enriched my life
that I could not allow her
to pass into oblivion.
So I incorporated her programs
back into my own.
I have transferred
her memories to me.
Mr. Data, will you
take your position.
Mr. Crusher,
lay in a course
for the Starbase on Otar II.
WESLEY:
Course is set, sir.
PICARD:
Engage.