Captain's Log,
Stardate 43685.2:
As part of
an exchange program,
we are taking aboard
a Klingon officer
to return the recent visit
of Commander Riker
to the Cruiser Pagh.
We must take care of him
while he's with us.
Commander Kurn is accorded all
the rights and responsibilities
due to a first officer
on board this ship.
If he should feel
patronized in any way...
Oh, I'm sure we'd know.
One does not patronize
a Klingon warrior.
Your experience on board
the Pagh will prove invaluable
during the Commander's tour.
Be sure the crew are prepared
for any unusual orders.
The Klingons
are very thorough.
I'm sure Commander Kurn
has studied for his assignment
just as I did
when I served with them.
I understand he requested
the Enterprise specifically.
Commander Kurn is ready
for transport, Captain.
Energize.
Welcome aboard
the Enterprise, Commander.
I'm Captain Picard.
This is Commander
William Riker.
He will be yielding
the first officer's position
to you during your tour.
You are relieved.
May I take my station, sir?
I thought I might show you
to your quarters first.
I am ready for duty, sir.
I ask that I be allowed
to take my station.
Very well.
If you will accompany us
to the Bridge.
I am Kurn,
commander rank,
Klingon Defense Force.
You will address me
as "Commander" or "sir"
at all times.
I am fully aware
of all Starfleet regulations
and they will be strictly
adhered to by all personnel
while I am in command.
It is my intention to bring
a sense of discipline
that you may not
be accustomed to.
With your permission,
of course, Captain.
Oh, by all means, Commander.
I have studied
all of your Starfleet records.
Impressive.
We shall see if you live up
to your reputations.
( whispering )
Do you wish to speak
Acting Ensign Wesley Crusher?
No, sir, Commander, sir.
The crew awaits your orders,
Captain.
Then take us to the outer
cometary cloud, Commander.
Set course 114,
mark 230.
One-third
impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Execute.
Engaged.
Increasing to one-third
impulse power, sir.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Mind if I join you?
No, sir.
Is there something wrong, Wes?
Commander Kurn, perhaps?
He just doesn't
seem to like me.
I can't do anything
right for him.
Every time I respond
to an order,
he jumps down my throat.
I don't know
what I'm doing wrong.
Problem, Geordi?
Yes, sir.
It's our
new First Officer.
I take it he found something
wrong with Engineering.
Just the entire section.
He pulled
a surprise inspection
in the middle of
a maintenance cycle.
I tried to explain
it to him, but...
But he wouldn't listen.
We're all going to be doing
double shifts down there
just to get ready
for the next inspection.
( sighs )
His style of command
is just different.
Klingons believe in obedience
and a strict formality
of command.
Yeah, but this isn't
a Klingon vessel.
He's going to have
to loosen up, Commander.
WESLEY:
And it's not just us.
He's been leaning into everybody
pretty hard, except...
Except the one guy
who wouldn't really mind it.
( console beeping )
Sensors picking up asteroidal
debris ahead, Commander.
Can you identify
the coordinates, Mr. Worf?
Bearing 001,
mark .03
Range--
300,000 kilometers.
Excellent.
Please scan the asteroid field
for me, Lieutenant,
and report.
Approximately
2,000 small objects.
None directly in
our flight path, sir.
So no course correction
is necessary.
Is that what you are saying?
It should not be needed, sir.
Very good, Lieutenant.
You handled that well.
Yes?
Commander.
Captain's mess?
Yes.
Resume.
Your knowledge of
our systems and procedures
is very impressive.
Sir.
I would like to make
one suggestion, sir.
A suggestion?
When I served aboard the Pagh,
the hardest part for me
was recognizing and adapting
to the demands of the crew.
They needed an iron hand.
I imagine it must be
very difficult for you
to work with a crew
that is... so different.
I would be happy
to guide you in that regard
if it would be helpful.
No, Commander,
it wouldn't.
This is not
a Klingon ship, sir.
No, Commander,
it is not.
If it were a Klingon ship,
I would have killed you
for offering your suggestion.
How long has
this bird been dead?
It appears to have been lying
in the sun for quite some time.
Well, it's not dead.
It's been replicated and...
You do understand that
we cook most of our foods.
Ah, yes, I was told
to prepare for that.
I shall try some of your
burned, replicated bird meat.
I have attempted
to select a menu
that will allow you to sample
a variety of dishes, Commander.
Try some caviar.
( growls )
The odor is not palatable.
What is it?
The unhatched eggs
of a large, scaleless...
Later, Data.
A fish, Commander.
A delicacy from
the Caspian Sea on Earth.
It's a favorite of mine.
Our replicator has
never done it justice,
but I manage to store a few
cases for special occasions.
I am... honored, Captain.
Are you adjusting
to your new environment,
Commander?
I find the constraints
a bit difficult to conform to.
Just a short while ago,
I had to stop myself
from killing Commander Riker.
( laughs )
I believed he was
trying to communicate
the crew's sense of discomfort
with my style of command.
Under normal circumstances,
I would consider that
a challenge to my authority.
One of the aims of
the exchange program, Commander,
is for us all
to learn tolerance.
As for my crew,
it may be healthy
to shake up the status quo
occasionally.
The Commander
certainly appears
to have the crew
on its toes, sir.
And then some.
No offense, sir.
None taken.
I never kill anyone at
the supper table, Mr. La Forge.
Don't you like it, Commander?
Our food has much
more taste to it.
While I'm sure
this is well-prepared,
it is much too bland
for the stomach
of a Klingon.
It seems to agree with Worf.
Yes.
( door chimes )
Enter.
'el.
Permission to
speak freely, sir.
For what purpose?
I have questions
I wish to pose.
Are your quarters
so comfortable?
They serve me.
This entire ship
seems built on
comfort, relaxation...
being at ease.
It is not the ship
of a warrior.
Not the ship of a Klingon.
You cannot ask these questions
within the boundaries
of protocol?
They are of a...
personal nature, sir.
Permission granted.
Pose your questions.
I wish to know
if I have given you offense.
I am not human.
If you had given offense,
you would not need to ask.
Perhaps I have not performed
my duties to your satisfaction.
I find you to be
a capable Starfleet officer,
a credit to your ship.
Yet, you dishonor me
at every opportunity.
Have I?
I did not know that being
polite to a Starfleet officer
would bring dishonor to him.
I am a Klingon.
Really?
Perhaps your blood
has thinned
in this environment.
I simply didn't
want to hurt you.
( yells )
mev yap!
So your blood is not
so thin after all.
I am a Klingon!
If you doubt it,
a demonstration can be arranged.
That is the response
of a Klingon.
The response I
would expect...
from my older brother.
I was barely a year old
when you left
for the Khitomer Outpost.
You, our mother and father
were not going to stay long.
It was decided that I
did not need to go.
I was left to stay with
our father's friend, Lorgh,
until your return.
You never did.
The Starfleet officer
that rescued me
was told by the Klingon
High Command that...
I had no living relatives.
They assumed that I was killed
with the family at Khitomer.
Lorgh had no sons.
He took me into his family.
It was not until I reached
the Age of Ascension
that I was told the truth.
So you asked
to serve aboard
the Enterprise to watch me.
It was an excellent
opportunity
to see what kind
of Klingon you were
or if you were
Klingon at all.
Your deception
offends me, brother.
It should.
But it was required.
To satisfy your curiosity.
No, much more.
You are the eldest son.
The challenge is
yours to make.
Challenge?
The Klingon High Council
has judged our father
a traitor to the Empire.
What are
the allegations, Worf?
My father is accused
of aiding and abetting
the Romulan attack
on the Khitomer Outpost.
The attack in which
he himself was killed?
But why now,
after 20 years?
I do not know,
Captain.
I will hear the evidence
when I arrive.
The charge has
been made by Duras,
the son of my father's
greatest rival.
Our family name
will be disgraced
for seven generations.
It is my responsibility
to clear his name
or answer for his crimes.
Answer for them?
The family of a Klingon warrior
is responsible for his actions
and he is responsible
for theirs.
If I fail in my challenge,
I will be executed.
Will you grant my leave,
Captain?
No.
If I understand correctly,
a Starfleet officer,
a respected member of my crew,
could be accused
of a capital crime.
Your actions in this matter
will reflect on this ship
and on the Federation.
Therefore, it seems
only appropriate
that your Captain
should be at your side
while you make
your challenge.
I'm sure you would do
no less for me.
Commander Kurn.
Sir.
We're changing course.
Set coordinates
for the First City
of the Klingon
Imperial Empire.
We arrive within the hour.
Yes.
The Council will receive you at
high sun in the Great Hall of...
I know the procedure
for the challenge.
You'll need a cha'DIch
to defend you.
While you are accused,
you will not be allowed combat.
I would be honored
if you chose me.
I ask you to stand with me,
to be my cha'DIch.
jIlajneS.
ghIj qet jaghmeyjaj.
The two sons of Mogh--
together, we'll restore
the family honor.
No, for the proceedings,
you will not reveal
your true father.
I must.
You will not.
Because it would mean my death
as well if you fail.
A Klingon's honor means
more to him than his life.
Perhaps your human values
have clouded your judgment.
I insist.
On this ship,
you are my Commander
and I obey.
In council chambers,
you are my cha'DIch.
You do not insist.
You obey.
Yes, brother.
( speaking Klingon )
( loud announcement
in Klingon )
I am Worf, son of Mogh.
I have come to challenge
the lies that have been
spoken of my father.
( excited murmuring )
Worf, son of Mogh,
you have challenged
the judgment of the Council.
Are you prepared to answer
for this if you fail?
Yes, with my life.
Why do you come before us,
Commander?
I am Kurn,
son of... Lorgh.
I will stand
by Worf's side.
I am cha'DIch.
Hmm.
( grunts )
You claim a birthright
you have forsaken.
I have not forsaken
my heritage.
I am Klingon.
My heart is of this world.
My blood is as yours.
Yet, you come to us
wearing a child's uniform.
And you bring outsiders
to our Great Hall.
I am here at
my own request.
I am Captain Jean-Luc
Picard of the Enterprise.
Your words
mean nothing here.
Duras, let him speak.
Lieutenant Worf has
served under my command
with distinction.
He has earned my admiration
and my respect.
It is my greatest wish
that this Council,
in its wisdom,
will clear his family name
and return him to duty.
The trust of a commanding
officer is admirable.
Council has noted it.
Speak the accusation.
For many turns,
the truth about Khitomer
hath lain dormant,
unknown.
Now the truth
has been revealed.
The traitor, Mogh, sent
the defense access codes
to the Romulan
patrol ships,
allowing them to
destroy the outpost.
Thousands died
on Khitomer.
My father died on Khitomer.
Their deaths must be avenged.
( crowd murmuring )
Your father
was a traitor.
By posing this challenge,
you are a traitor.
You will not wear
the emblems of our people.
You are a fool
and your challenge can only
result in a fool's death.
It is a good day
to die, Duras.
And the day is not yet over.
Council stands in recess.
We will return
for the Mek'ba.
The evidence
will be presented.
Qapla'!
Mr. Data...
find out everything you can
about the destruction
of the Khitomer Outpost.
Cross-reference
with Romulan tactics
and strategic information
on the region.
And request access to the
Klingon central information net.
Computer, presentation overview
of Klingon custom and law
pertaining to
familial accountability.
COMPUTER:
Accessing.
In my ready room.
Worf.
I would speak with you.
Alone.
You should not have
brought the challenge.
There was no risk to you.
What does it matter?
I am Klingon.
Of that,
I have no question.
But your life
in the Federation
would not be affected
by this judgment.
My father...
Is dead.
He died long ago.
I knew your father,
served with him.
This is not how I wanted
to remember him.
We must let
the past be
and protect
what we have now.
If you leave
before the Mek'ba,
no shame will
come upon you.
Return to your ship.
Go back to your life.
The challenge
will be forgotten.
Why would you ask me
to lay aside
the honor of my father,
my family?
Are these the words
of the Council?
I will not
be questioned by you.
Leave now,
or you, too, will be
condemned as a traitor.
What Federation starship was
the closest to the Khitomer
at the time of the attack?
DATA:
The USS Intrepid was the first
ship on the scene, sir.
Contact Starfleet.
Request all logs
of the Intrepid.
Riker to Dr. Crusher.
Crusher here.
I want you to look
over the medical records
from all the rescue vessels
that responded to
the Khitomer massacre.
See if there's any information
on the aftermath that
might help us.
CRUSHER:
Understood.
I should have known.
Worf was right.
It is a good day to die.
The time has not yet come.
It does not have
to come for many turns.
I know who you are, Kurn,
son of Mogh.
What?
It was a wise choice
to hide your family name.
Do not err now
by embracing it again,
for you only embrace death.
We shall see.
Worf has made a choice
and he will die for it,
but you can still be safe.
Let him stand alone.
He is my brother.
I will not betray him!
Then you will die for him.
( growls )
( growling and grunting )
( grunts in pain )
( speaking Klingon )
What kind of a weapon
makes a vicious wound like that?
It is a kut'luch,
the ceremonial weapon
of an assassin.
Fortunately, his metabolic
recovery is phenomenal.
He will be all right.
It does not matter.
We should have let him die.
Now that Duras
knows his bloodlines...
we will both be executed.
You sound like you've
already lost, Worf.
Commander, I have discovered
the basis of the charges
against Worf's father.
Apparently, the Klingons
recently captured
a Romulan ship with logs
that provided new information
on the Khitomer attack.
They clearly indicate
a transmission from the outpost
to the Romulan ship
moments before
the shields went down.
From Worf's father?
They do correspond to
Mogh's personal security code.
How can we be sure those records
haven't been falsified?
Well, we can cross-check
them against the Intrepid's
sensor logs.
I will try,
but the Intrepid was at
the edge of sensor range
during the attack
and we cannot be certain
if the scan was complete.
Looks like a pretty good
match-up, Data.
Both the Intrepid
and the Romulan logs
show a series of distress
signals from Khitomer.
What happened
there?
Those are gaps
in the Intrepid's logs.
Missing information
due to the range.
That is where Mogh's alleged
transmission should be.
Right in the middle of the gap?
Wait a second, Data.
Back up.
Just before
the Intrepid's gap begins,
the timebase on both files
are in perfect sync.
But look.
Look at what happens
to the signal
after the shields
are dropped.
They are no longer
synchronous.
Commander, somebody's
been rewriting history.
I do not pretend to fully
understand the nuances
of your world's law
and culture, Lieutenant,
but I do understand when someone
is trying to hide something.
K'mpec urged me
to drop my challenge,
abandon my family honor.
It was impossible to believe
I was hearing a Klingon speak.
Obviously, they did not expect
and never wanted this challenge.
You're getting close
to something, Lieutenant.
Something they care
a great deal about protecting.
If it is true,
it is not just Duras
but the High Council itself
that is my enemy.
Captain...
I must choose
another cha'DIch.
I would like your permission
to ask one of the crew.
Well, of course, Lieutenant.
Choose whomever you wish.
Then I would ask you
to stand with me.
You may refuse
with no dishonor.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
I appreciate the gesture,
but I know that there are
stronger and younger men
from whom to choose.
I can think of no one
I would rather have at my side.
jIlajneS.
ghIj qet jaghmeyjaj.
I accept.
( announcement in Klingon )
My challenge will proceed.
No threats, no treachery
will stop it.
Not even a trap set
for my cha'DIch
by a coward.
Duras!
I will not hear lies
from the son of a traitor.
Keep your place,
Picard!
This is my place.
He is now my cha'DIch.
This is not your world, human.
You do not
command here.
I'm not here to command.
Then you must
be ready to fight.
Something Starfleet
does not teach you.
You may test that assumption
at your convenience.
I've got something.
Worf was not the only survivor
of the Khitomer massacre.
Another child?
No, a Klingon woman
was found with Worf.
RIKER:
Kahlest. Who was she?
I don't know, but the report
said she was severely injured,
was transferred to
Starbase 24 for treatment--
that was when she was
separated from Worf--
and after her recovery,
she returned home.
We've got to find her
if she's still alive.
Data, scan the Klingon
central net.
See if there's
any record of her.
DURAS:
The Romulans lowered the
outpost's shields themselves.
They were given
the defense access code.
The record
clearly shows
the Romulan patrol ship
receiving a personal
transmission from Mogh
seconds before
the shields fell.
RIKER:
Riker to Captain Picard.
Stand by.
The Khitomer Commander
noted in his log
that Mogh had been
acting suspiciously...
Go ahead, Number One.
We've located another survivor
of the Khitomer massacre--
a woman who was
found with Worf.
Her name is Kahlest.
She resides in the Old Quarter
of the First City.
Well done. Picard out.
DURAS:
...Another witness testified
that Mogh often spoke
of his admiration
for the Romulans--
their culture,
their women.
Mogh betrayed us
and 4,000 Klingons
died on Khitomer.
Only the son
of Mogh survived.
K'mpec.
May we have
a short recess?
Len'mat.
Have you heard of
a woman called Kahlest?
She was my ghojmok,
my nurse.
Then it's possible
she was an eyewitness
to your father's
activities on Khitomer.
But she died in the attack.
No, she survived.
She's living
in the Old Quarter.
I'm going to find her.
It is too dangerous.
You must not go alone.
Hey, I'm your cha'DIch.
Kahlest?
What do you want?
Your help.
No.
You don't even know
what I want.
You are cha'DIch.
I know.
Then you also know
that Worf's life
is at stake.
I cannot help.
I am dead.
A long time dead.
Were you with
Worf's father
just before the
attack on Khitomer?
No.
My life ended on Khitomer.
I served a proud family,
a strong house.
All that is gone.
Worf is not gone.
The family you served
needs you again.
I cannot help.
Was his father
a traitor?
No.
Mogh was loyal to the Emperor.
Mogh suspected someone
of plotting with the Romulans
and followed them
to Khitomer.
Who?
Who was the traitor?
I do not know.
Then we have no way
to prove Mogh's innocence...
and Worf will die
as the son of a traitor.
You must leave now, cha'DIch.
I am dead.
( yelling in Klingon )
( groaning )
My appreciation, madam.
You are brave, cha'DIch.
Worf chose well.
Kahlest, would they
recognize you?
Would they know who you are?
K'mpec would
remember Kahlest.
I caught his eye
back then,
but he was too fat.
Come back with me.
They won't know
how much you know.
It may shake loose the truth.
I will come.
DURAS:
The evidence is clear.
I would ask that
the judgment stand.
Let Worf be
condemned as a son
of a traitor
to the Empire.
( Klingons growling )
Worf, son of Mogh,
the judgment of...
K'mpec!
The Mek'ba is
not complete.
I bring an eyewitness
to the Khitomer massacre.
One who has
new evidence, K'mpec.
Len'mat!
What is it you think
you know, old woman?
Do not answer.
It is the rules
of the Mek'ba
that evidence be presented
in open council.
She will die before
she gives evidence.
Be silent, Duras.
Would you kill an old woman
to cover your dishonor?
Yes.
It is your dishonor
we are protecting here,
isn't it, Duras?
I have no reluctance
to kill you, human.
Are you prepared to hear
her evidence in open council?
Obviously, we would not.
Kahlest...
you can go now.
It is good
to see you again.
You are still fat, K'mpec.
I asked you to leave.
To let this challenge
go unanswered.
But you did not
hear my words,
and now it has
come to this.
Why did you judge
my father guilty
when you knew he was not?!
Someone had to be blamed.
The warriors who captured
the Romulan ship
had learned of the treachery.
But only the Council knew
whose security code
had been transmitted.
Ja'rod...
father... of Duras.
This Ha'DIBah should have
been fed to the dogs!
His family is powerful.
If the truth were known,
it would shatter the Council.
Most certainly plunge
us into civil war.
You were in Starfleet.
We did not expect you
to challenge the judgment.
Nor did we know
there was another son of Mogh.
Worf's challenge
is successful.
The honor of his family
must be restored.
You do not understand.
His challenge was defeated
before he ever made it.
You will not be allowed
to present this evidence.
The judgment stands.
You will be condemned.
So will your brother.
There is no other way now.
You admit the truth
and yet expect him
to accept punishment?
What does this say
of an Empire
who holds honor so dear?
The Empire will not
be destroyed
for one family's honor.
Unacceptable, K'mpec.
You have no say
in this, cha'DIch.
I speak now as the Captain
of the USS Enterprise
and Lieutenant Worf's
commanding officer.
You will not execute
a member of my crew,
nor will I turn his brother
over to you.
This is not
the Federation, Picard.
If you defy
an order of
the High Council,
the alliance
with the Federation
could fall to dust.
The alliance of the Federation
is not based on lies, K'mpec.
Protect your secrets
if you must,
but you will not
sacrifice these men.
I will die
for the Empire.
Lieutenant...
The cha'DIch
will be silent!
Allow my brother
to return to his life.
Only you need know
his true bloodline.
Not acceptable.
His honor would
demand revenge.
If you allow him to live,
I will give you something
that will serve your purpose
far more than my death.
I will accept
discommendation.
Ah...
You...
would do this
in open council?
It would be the same
as admitting
your father's guilt, Worf.
So be it.
Your heart is Klingon.
It will be done.
What has been said here
will never be
spoken of again.
You are the son of a traitor.
Now I am ready.
Why is he doing this?
I was prepared to die.
Worf wants you to live.
The name of your father
must someday be cleared.
He needs you alive
with your honor intact.
But to do this...
There will be
another day, Commander.
Do not forget what
he does here today.
Do not let your
children forget.
( crowd murmuring )
tlhIH ghIj...
jIHyoj.
biHnuch.
You must also...
brother.