PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43714.1.
We have finally succeeded
in eradicating
the Phyrox plague
on Cor Caroli V
and will soon be preparing
to leave orbit
and proceed
to our next mission--
a rendezvous with the USS Hood
to assist in their terraforming
efforts on Browder IV.
( sighing )
( vibrating hum )
( electrical pulsing)
( electrical crackling )
( beeping )
Commander, ship's sensors detect
an abnormal energy reading
in the Captain's quarters.
Type?
Undetermined.
Riker to Captain Picard.
Security team
to Captain's quarters.
( fritzing beep )
Picard to Enterprise.
Anyone receiving
this transmission
please respond.
( beeping )
Security override.
Priority one.
Is something the matter,
Lieutenant?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( gasping )
It's all right,
it's all right.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Ca... Captain...?
Picard of the Enterprise.
Captain Picard.
We studied your missions
at the academy.
Mitena Haro, first year cadet,
Starfleet Academy.
Cadet Haro.
Perhaps you
can explain
what this is all about.
Unfortunately, I can't,
Mister...?
Tholl.
Kova Tholl, of Mizar II.
Well, Mr. Tholl, all I know is
that I've been brought here
against my will.
Wherever "here" is.
The same thing
happened to me, sir.
I-I was alone, studying,
and... I fainted.
When I came to...
It was about three days ago.
And you, sir?
I've been here
12 days
possibly more.
I had been meditating privately
and for no reason whatever,
I lost consciousness.
What can you tell me
about our captors?
Nothing.
They've never shown themselves.
Four sleeping areas.
That implies we may be joined
by another captive.
It's edible
but I wouldn't
call it food.
Hmm...
I wouldn't
touch that.
Why not?
If it's the door lock
the combination is too complex
to hit at random.
I tried it... and was punished.
Punished?
How?
Severe pain.
Some sort of energy beam.
I won't go near
that panel again.
( communications beep )
WORF:
Sir, the Hood has arrived
at the rendezvous point.
They are expecting us
in 36 hours.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Mr. Data
the nearest pulsar
is in the Lonka Cluster
is it not?
Correct, sir.
What do we know
about that pulsar?
A great deal, sir.
It is a rotating neutron star
of approximately
4.356 solar masses...
Mr. Crusher, how long would it
take us to get there?
At warp seven,
34 minutes, sir.
Mr. Crusher,
make it so.
Sir?
Set course for
the Lonka Cluster.
Warp two.
Aye, sir.
Sir, at warp two
we'll arrive at the pulsar
in 31 hours.
Thank you, Ensign.
Engage.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Will we be delaying
our rendezvous with
the Hood, sir?
We may have to,
Number One.
Lieutenant, contact
the Hood and inform
them of our delay.
Aye, Commander.
Belay that order.
There will be no
further communication
off this ship
without my prior
authorization.
Commander, may I
have
a word with you?
Mr. Data, you
have the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
Number One, you know
I like to keep you
well informed
as to the nature
of our missions.
Yes, sir.
And if I don't inform you,
there is a reason.
Well, I don't like
keeping you in the dark
but for the next few days
I may not be able to be
as communicative as usual.
It may make things
difficult for you.
Don't worry
about me, sir.
I can handle it.
And the crew?
You can count on
all of us, sir.
I appreciate that,
Number One.
( door opens and closes )
( rhythmic beeping )
Picard
what are you doing?
I'm attempting
to let our captors know
we possess intelligence.
You don't think
they already know that?
They can hear us talking.
Yes, but they
may not realize
that we're communicating
through language.
Captain Picard is
letting them know
that we comprehend
mathematics
by tapping out
the first six
prime numbers.
I know what he's doing.
I'm trying to understand why.
It is imperative
that we communicate
with our abductors;
find out what they want.
Obviously, they want us.
Obviously.
But why?
What makes our captors
choose us?
What makes us special?
I couldn't say, Captain.
I'm certainly not special.
I am just one cadet.
What's your best
area of study?
Impulse propulsion systems.
I'm very good
with field coils.
Good enough to
be useful to
our abductors?
I don't know. Maybe.
But if they needed
an engineer, sir
why didn't they
take a real one?
Why pick a
Starfleet cadet?
That I can't answer.
( sighs )
The Bolians
are maintaining
an uneasy truce
with the Moropa
are they not?
That's right.
But this does not look like
Moropa technology
and even assuming
the Moropa wanted me
what would they want
with either of you?
I've never even heard
of the Moropa.
My race has no enemies.
None?
In the last 300 years
of Mizarian history
your planet
has been conquered six times.
And we've survived
by not resisting.
Mizarians value peace
above confrontation.
And you have no idea
who might have done this?
No, I can't
think of anyone
who bears malice
toward my race.
Against you personally?
You can't mean to
suggest that someone
with a personal
grudge against me
has gone to all
this trouble?
I'm not
suggesting anything.
I'm merely trying
to come up
with some explanation
for your abduction.
I am sorry, Picard.
I can't give you one.
I am neither important enough
to hold for ransom
nor radical enough
to be dangerous.
I'm a simple
public servant.
Nevertheless, Mr. Tholl...
( transporter hum )
( groaning )
( ferocious growling )
Stop!
We mean you no harm.
( snarling growl )
We are prisoners, like yourself.
We are not the enemy.
Who has done this?
We don't know.
We were brought here
the same way you were.
Our captors refuse
to show themselves.
I don't trust you.
You must trust us.
We wish only to return
to our worlds.
Were you abducted from Chalna?
You know my planet?
Oh, yes.
I visited there 12 years ago
while commanding the Stargazer.
RIKER:
A five and 20.
Ouch.
If it's too rich,
Geordi, fold.
I'm thinking,
I'm thinking.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Counselor, gentlemen.
Forgive this intrusion.
I was, uh, just passing by.
You are always
welcome, Captain.
I was wondering, Mr. La Forge
what's our engine
efficiency status?
Operating at 93%, sir.
Hmm. That's very good
but I would like
to increase the
efficiency to 95%.
No problem, Captain.
I'll get right on it.
Oh, that's not
an order.
Uh, you can get to it later.
I don't want to disrupt
your recreation.
No, Captain.
It's... it's no problem.
Lady Luck left me long ago.
Would you care
to join us, Captain?
We have an opening.
Um... I'll just observe,
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
Counselor, 20.
( chips rattling )
A pair of threes.
Flush, queen high.
That beats my fours.
Well played,
Counselor.
Could I have a word
for just a moment?
Certainly, sir.
Forgive me,
gentlemen.
I'll return your player
to you in a moment.
Counselor, I, uh...
I wanted to ask you
about the crew.
How are they reacting
to our sudden change in course?
I sense
no unusual reactions, Captain.
After all,
such a change is hardly
out of the ordinary.
They're not curious
or concerned as to why?
They're curious, yes,
but concerned? No.
They trust you.
How far do you think
that trust goes?
Sir?
Oh, I know, Counselor
that the crew has always had
full confidence in me, but...
what if it were
to change?
Well, I'd inform you,
sir, of course.
Thank you, Counselor.
My given name is Esoqq.
It means "fighter."
I'll bet half the names
in the Chalna language
mean "fighter."
Mizarians--
your names all
mean "surrender."
We are a peaceful race--
a race of thinkers.
A race of cowards.
And you?
I don't know
your people.
I am Mitena Haro
of Bolarus IX.
Who would want to imprison
a child?
I am not a child.
Esoqq, I have been
trying to determine
if we have
a common enemy--
someone with a reason
for confining us here.
There are Chalnoth
who would kill me if they could
but kidnap?
There is no reason.
You have many enemies?
None of consequence.
I've slain all the ones
who matter.
That shocks you, Bolian?
A little.
And you?
No, no, I'm
not surprised.
I've heard about your race.
You're uncivilized.
You have no laws,
no system of government.
The Chalnoth have no use
for laws or governments.
We are strong.
We obey no one.
You live in anarchy,
murdering one another.
That mentality
may get us all killed.
And you may be the first.
Both of you--
this is getting us nowhere.
Neither is asking us
useless questions, Picard.
But if you must
pursue the topic
how long have you
and the Romulans
been adversaries?
For quite a while, Mr. Tholl.
Oh, I am perfectly willing
to entertain the hypothesis
that our captors are Romulans
but what would the Romulans
want with you?
My brainpower, perhaps.
It's well known
that my species
possesses superior
intelligence and, uh...
I am considered among
the brightest of my people.
HARO:
And the least
modest.
( sniffing )
What is this?
PICARD:
Food.
The only food?
It would seem so.
Poison!
Does this mean
there is nothing here
for you to eat?
You.
No, don't even think that.
Picard, you won't let him...
Esoqq, how long can you go
without food?
Three days,
perhaps four.
No longer?
No longer.
Well, all your tests
indicate the same results.
You are in great shape.
I've never felt better.
I see.
Then why did you come in?
Your annual physical
isn't due for another month.
Well, usually you
have to remind me,
and badger me
and finally order
me to report.
For once, I thought I'd
save you the trouble.
Jean-Luc, be honest
with your doctor.
Are there any warning signs
or symptoms
that you haven't told me about?
( deep sigh )
As far as I know,
I'm perfectly healthy.
Well then, return to your post.
Will you have dinner
with me tonight?
In Ten-Forward?
What about my quarters?
More intimate.
Jean-Luc, you are
full of surprises today.
I take that
to be a "yes."
Picard, is it wise
to attempt an escape?
It's imperative.
Why?
Our captors haven't
mistreated us.
We've been kidnapped,
locked in a room.
You don't think
that's mistreatment?
They haven't hurt
us, have they?
I think we should
just wait
until we find out
what they want.
Be patient.
We can no longer afford
to be patient.
Unless we act soon,
Esoqq will starve.
If we antagonize them
they may decide we're more
trouble than we're worth
kill us and go
capture another four.
I agree,
that's a risk
but I see
no alternative.
Well... I refuse to help.
As you wish, Mr. Tholl.
We must get
inside this panel.
ESOQQ:
Not very sturdy.
Stand back, Haro.
( Esoqq growling )
The design is simple.
Cross-circuiting
the door mechanism
should be easy.
Make it so.
Yes, sir.
I think I've got it.
( door hums )
( groaning )
I warned you.
Out with it, Jean-Luc.
Out with what?
Whatever has been on your
mind all evening long.
Hmm. Has it been that apparent?
Mm-hmm.
How well you know me.
After all this
time, I ought to.
Well, it's true.
I have been preoccupied.
I know that's not
very flattering to you
but I have been
thinking about us
and about the choices
I've made.
We both have
made choices.
And I've been wondering
if they were the right ones.
Sometimes, I feel
we've allowed our positions
to isolate us.
Our positions
necessitate a degree
of professional
detachment.
But.... there's a danger
in becoming too detached--
of never permitting ourselves
to get closer.
Is that what you want, Jean-Luc?
To get closer?
You're a very attractive woman.
And you're
a very attractive man.
But we both know
it's not as simple as that.
Would it be simpler
if I were not
your commanding officer?
Simpler, perhaps.
But that's not the only issue.
I guess, right now
I'm comfortable
with our relationship
just the way it is.
( soft, romantic music begins)
Would you care to dance?
I thought you didn't dance.
On special occasions.
I don't think
I told you
but I'm glad you're back
on the Enterprise.
I missed our friendship.
I did, too.
Jean-Luc...
if I didn't
know you better
I would think you were
playing games with me.
Are you sorry
you came tonight?
I didn't say that.
Good.
Because I'm delighted
that you did.
But perhaps we should
call it a night.
Good night.
I warned you
not to provoke our captors.
The next beams
might be lethal.
Not to you.
You moved far from the door.
Of course I did.
Being stunned once was enough.
You claimed you were hit
by the stun beam
before the rest of us arrived.
You could be lying.
Maybe our enemy
is watching us
from inside.
Are you accusing me
of collaborating
with our abductors?
Collaboration
is what your species does best.
You did try
to talk us
out of attempting to escape.
For all we know
you may be our captor.
( laughs )
Impossible.
I'm a Mizarian.
My people
are not aggressive.
How can we be sure
you're a Mizarian?
You could be an impostor.
This is nonsense.
What if you're an impostor?
Esoqq was the last one
to appear.
And he is the only one
with a weapon.
Keep talking and I will use it.
Tholl, our captors
have transporters.
They have stun beams.
It is hardly likely
that they would try
to hold us at bay
with a knife.
Well then, maybe
she's the impostor.
She could have triggered
the stun beams deliberately.
I was hit, too.
To forestall
suspicion.
You were very quick
to volunteer.
PICARD:
Tholl, I asked her
to open the door.
You ordered her, you mean.
You've been giving orders
from the moment you got here--
trying to make everyone
do what you want.
Tholl, what I want
is for everyone to escape!
Why should we
believe you?
Captain Picard's put his life
at stake for others many times.
The primitive culture
on Mintaka III.
The Wogneer creatures
in the Ordek Nebula.
And Cor Caroli V.
Right.
Helping to cure
the Phyrox plague.
And how do we know
this is the heroic
Captain Picard?
We have no proof
of his identity.
THOLL:
You've wasted our time
with failed attempts
to communicate with them
or escape.
Is that your task?
To keep us busy
so we're off guard?
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Although we're still 18 hours
from the Lonka Pulsar
the Captain has ordered us
to slow to one-half impulse.
He has offered no explanation.
Here.
I don't know why we're going
to this pulsar.
And creeping up on it
at half-impulse
makes even less sense.
The Captain has given
unusual orders before.
I know
but this is different--
he's different.
I can't put my finger on it
but I'm worried.
The Captain does seem...
detached from his emotions.
( door opens )
Captain.
Mr. La Forge, we are operating
at 96% engine efficiency.
Well done.
Thank you, sir.
When we arrive
at the pulsar
I shall require everyone
at their best.
I know that I can rely
on both of you.
Of course, Captain.
Excellent.
An ale for me...
and for my officers.
In fact, ales for everyone.
( appreciative murmuring )
MAN:
Thank you, Captain.
Here's to the finest crew
in Starfleet.
MAN:
Hear, hear.
( light applause and laughter)
You know, back when I was
in the academy
we would follow every toast
with a song.
I wonder if I can...
Oh, yes.
( clears throat )
♪ Come cheer up, my lads ♪
♪ 'Tis to glory we steer ♪
♪ To find something new
in this wonderful year ♪
♪ To honor we call you
as free men, not slaves ♪
♪ But who are so free
as the sons of the waves? ♪
♪ Heart of oak are our ships,
jolly tars are our men ♪
♪ We always are ready,
steady, boy, steady ♪
♪ We'll fight and we'll conquer
again and again ♪
♪ Come cheer up, my lads ♪
♪ 'Tis to glory we steer ♪
♪ To find something new
in this wonderful year... ♪
Commander, what's
the Captain up to?
That's not the Captain I know.
♪ ...So free
as the sons of the waves ♪
♪ Heart of oak are our ships,
jolly tars are our men... ♪
We're on a mission
that has no apparent purpose.
In itself, I can accept that.
All of us can, because
the Captain says it's important
and we trust him.
Then, he runs the crew
through efficiency drills
for the first time
in my tour of duty
but he says we need them,
so we need them--
because we trust our Captain.
But we also have a Captain
singing drinking songs
with his men.
A captain who's come to the
poker game for the first time.
And he was very odd
with me afterwards.
He wanted me to warn him
if the crew started
to lose confidence in him.
Any signs of mental stress
or trauma?
He came in
for a physical
with no word from me.
Anything unusual, Doctor?
Every test result
identical
to his last physical...
which is kind of unusual
in itself, actually.
Almost as though
he wanted to establish
that there was nothing wrong.
There was one other thing.
He asked me to dinner
in his cabin
and it was
a very unusual evening.
( sighs )
Which brings up
a very serious possibility.
What if there's an outside
influence at work here?
I detect no evidence
of telepathic coercion.
Commander, there is still one
fact we have not considered--
the abnormal energy reading
in the Captain's quarters
was never explained.
It is not enough
evidence
to justify mutiny.
Nobody has suggested
removing the Captain
from command.
Right now, all we
have are suspicions
not enough to act on.
The next move is his.
THOLL:
Well, Picard
prove to us
you're not the enemy.
I can't.
You're right,
Mr. Tholl.
Any one of us may be the enemy
and there is no way
to prove that we aren't.
But until we set aside
our mutual fears
and trust one another,
we have no hope of escape.
But, sir, how can we
trust each other?
She's right.
There may be
an enemy among us.
And what if there
is, Mr. Tholl?
Shall we continue
accusing one another
until hostility leads
to violence?
Shall we allow our suspicions
to destroy us?
Now, let's see if we can
override this stun mechanism.
Helm, take us in
to 20 million kilometers.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, divert enough
power to the shields
to offset the increased
radiation and magnetic fields.
Sir, at 20 million kilometers
our shields will
only be effective
for 18 minutes.
Noted, Mr. Data.
Captain, may I have
a word with you?
PICARD:
You have the Bridge,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
What is our mission?
I'm under no obligation
to tell you that.
If you don't, you force me
to take command of this vessel.
On what grounds?
You are endangering this ship
for no reason.
No reason you're aware of.
That's not
good enough.
Your behavior has been erratic.
Erratic enough
to justify mutiny?
Do you
honestly
believe
you have sufficient evidence
to convince a Board of Inquiry?
No, I don't.
But I can't let you risk
the lives of this crew.
Number One,
has it occurred to you
that you might be the one
with the problem?
I'm aware you've
been under stress
and I am willing to
let the matter drop
if you will report to Sick
Bay for a full examination.
Otherwise, I will have
to relieve you from duty.
Think about it.
( door opens and closes )
Cadet.
( clicking )
I may have
overloaded it, sir.
( grunting )
Mr. Tholl!
I still think this is a mistake.
Now what?
We're no better off
than when we started.
Captain, number four shield
has failed.
Increasing power to number three
shield to compensate.
Helm, move us closer.
Ten million kilometers.
DATA:
Sir, at that distance
the ship will not withstand the
magnetic fields and radiation.
We will not
survive.
Take us in, Mr. Crusher.
Belay that order.
You're relieved of duty,
Commander.
Mr. Worf, confine Mr. Riker
to his quarters.
Mr. Worf,
I gave you an order.
Maintain your position,
Lieutenant.
You're destroying yourself
and anyone foolish enough
to listen to you.
You've shown none of the concern
Captain Picard would
for the safety of this ship,
the welfare of his crew.
Mr. Worf, escort Commander Riker
from the Bridge.
Ensign Crusher,
take us away from this pulsar.
Heading 185 mark
32, full impulse.
Full impulse.
Aye, Commander.
Engage.
I hope you're
satisfied, Picard.
You've accomplished
nothing.
The sound of your voice
is beginning to anger me.
Well...
I think this charade
has gone far enough.
Don't you?
I don't understand.
Oh, yes, you do.
This isn't a holding cell.
It's a laboratory maze,
a carefully structured test.
It's an experiment to see
how well we react
under pressure.
How do you know?
It's the only explanation.
Look at the four of us.
We do have something
in common--
we all react differently
to authority.
You, the collaborator,
defer to whoever has control
you, the anarchist,
reject authority in any form.
I, a Starfleet Captain,
trained to command
and you...
a Starfleet cadet
sworn to obey a superior
officer's authority.
Our captors have placed us here
and have devised obstacles
for us to overcome.
They give us food
which Esoqq can't eat,
to make him a threat.
They give us a door
we can't open
until the four
of us cooperate
and each time
we succeed
they deal us reverses
to set us
against each other again
while you observe
our reactions.
Sir, I've been trying to help.
I found it unlikely
that a first-year cadet
would know of the Enterprise's
visit to Mintaka III
so I tested you.
Starfleet has classified
the Cor Caroli V plague
as "secret."
No cadet would
have knowledge
of that incident.
Captain...
So you may as well
drop this pretense.
I'm not playing any further.
I'm quitting this game.
As far as I am concerned
this experiment is over!
( voice resonating ):
You are correct, Captain Picard.
To further our knowledge
of alien interaction
we borrowed you, Tholl and Esoqq
and replaced you with replicas.
Replicas?
Our transporter is able
to replicate living matter
including the brain's many
trillion dendritic connections
where memory is stored.
THOLL:
You mean, there's
a copy of me
on Mizar II?
An impostor running my ship?
No longer.
Commander Riker has taken charge
of the Enterprise.
Our species is
telepathically linked.
We are all in
continual contact.
Much more efficient than your
primitive vocal communications.
We would like to...
pursue this study
but, of course, your awareness
of it would taint the results.
We will, therefore, return you
to your places of origin.
Captain!
Hold your
positions.
Take no action.
Why did you choose to study
the concepts
of authority
and leadership?
Because our species
has no such concepts.
As we are all identical
distinctions among ourselves
are meaningless.
Hence, we have
no leaders no followers.
We wanted to examine the nature
of command.
Our replicas
of Tholl and Esoqq
explored this issue
on Mizar II and on Chalna
just as our Picard
replica did
on the Enterprise.
Your responses were
most intriguing.
You have no right
to put us through this
just to satisfy your curiosity.
Why not?
Because kidnapping
is an immoral assault.
The rights of other races
must be respected.
This concept
of morality
is a very interesting
human characteristic.
We shall have
to study it
sometime.
Now, Mr. Worf.
( grunting in pain )
What is it?
Why do you hold us?
Because there is something else
you can learn.
With an alert crew
even our "primitive vocal
communications" are unnecessary.
With a single look,
I was able to inform my crew
that I wanted to hold you here.
But why?
Because I have decided
to conduct an experiment
of my own.
I want to see
how you react to
being imprisoned.
Captain, our species
cannot bear captivity.
We were merely
curious.
We meant no harm.
We did not, after all,
injure you in any way.
Imprisonment is an injury
regardless
of how you justify it.
( crying out )
( gasping )
( breathing slows )
PICARD:
And now that you have had
a taste of captivity
perhaps you will reconsider
the morality
of inflicting it
on others.
In any event, we
now know of your race
and we know how to imprison you.
Bear that in mind.
Now get off my ship.
Mr. Crusher, set
course to rendezvous
with the Hood. Warp 8.
Aye, sir. It's good
to have you back, sir.
Status, Number One?
Ship and crew
functioning normally, Captain.
Then my doppelganger caused
no serious damage?
The replica was convincing.
Very convincing, but...
not perfect.
Not perfect in what way?
Well, sir...
I find it hard to believe
that you're that good a singer.
Singer?
I look forward to reading
your report, Commander.
At least, I think I do.
( door opens )
Doctor.
Captain.
WESLEY:
Course laid in, sir.
Engage.