( people talking, laughing )
( birds singing )
COMPUTER:
Welcome to Risa.
All that is ours is yours.
We are looking for
the lodging chamber
of Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
A file scan reveals no record
of a Captain Picard
currently visiting Risa.
When is he expected
to arrive?
There is no arrival date
on file
for any such individual.
Could we have
been mistaken?
He will come.
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 43745.2.
We have departed Gemaris V
where, for the past two weeks
Captain Picard
has been serving as mediator
in a trade dispute
between the Gemarians
and their nearest neighbor,
the Dachlyds.
Welcome back, Deanna.
It's good
to be back.
The last two weeks
have been grueling.
I take it the Captain was able
to negotiate an agreement
mutually beneficial
to both parties.
He was.
I don't know how
he managed it.
The Gemarians
and the Dachlyds
are both incredibly
stubborn people.
The more difficult the task,
the sweeter the victory.
Go to warp four,
Mr. Bennett.
Set course
for Starbase 12.
Report.
Everything's
status quo, sir.
Very well.
If, um...
anyone needs me,
I'll be in my ready room.
Sir?
Congratulations.
About what?
About the trade agreement.
( grunts )
Is it my imagination or is
something bothering the Captain?
He has been under a great deal
of strain lately.
While we were on Gemaris, he ate
sparingly and slept even less.
Anything we can do?
Actually, I have
a solution in mind
but I doubt he'll agree to it.
What would that be?
Our Captain needs a vacation.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( door chimes )
Come!
Sir, it's been brought
to my attention
that one of the crew
is neglecting
his health again.
How so?
It's a classic case
of stress-related ailments
brought on by overwork--
exhaustion, irritability,
muscle spasms.
Yet he insists
on ignoring it.
It doesn't sound
too serious.
And I plan on keeping it
that way.
What's the treatment?
A week's shore leave.
Oh... impossible.
Jean-Luc, I could
make that an order.
But you won't.
Oh, Beverly, you know
I loathe vacations.
You loathe going on vacations.
Once you're there,
you have a marvelous time.
Why, you told me
that your four days
on Zytchin III
were wonderful.
I lied.
Look...
the Enterprise
is scheduled to spend a week
undergoing maintenance
overhaul at Starbase 12.
While there, I promise
that I will make full use
of available
recreational activity.
Watching some technician
fill deuterium tanks
is not my idea of fun.
I suppose I could find a few
hours to spend on the holodeck.
Oh, forget the holodeck.
Isn't there someplace special
you want to go?
The Astrophysics Center
on Icor IX
is holding a symposium
on rogue star clusters.
I had given serious thought
to attending.
The last thing you need
is serious thought.
Jean-Luc, why don't you go
someplace beautiful
where you can relax
and be pampered?
You deserve it.
I'll give it serious thought.
Captain...
Doctor... enough.
So, have you decided
where you're going yet?
Yes, I have, Number One.
Bridge.
No, I meant on
your shore leave.
Not you, too.
Halt. I know this perfect
little vacation spot.
In fact, it falls within the
coordinates of this sector.
How convenient,
except, Number One
I have absolutely no intention
of taking a holiday.
Is that clear?
Very clear.
Good. I'm glad we got that
straightened out. Resume.
The place is
called Risa
and believe me, Captain,
it is a paradise.
Warm tropical
breezes, exotic foods
nothing to do but sit
around all day, enjoy
the quiet and then...
the women.
The women.
Of course.
I'm sure you would find
their sybaritic outlook
on life very appealing.
Oh, I'm sure.
I'm glad to hear
you say so, sir.
Unfortunately,
this vessel is
about to undergo
extensive repairs
requiring my personal
supervision.
What about Risa?
Some other time, Number One.
Will, I just had
some terrific news.
Really?
There's an excellent
chance that my mother
may be joining us
on Starbase 12.
Your mother?
She's returning home from
a conference on Achrady VII
and she's going to try
to rearrange her schedule
so she can spend some time
visiting with us.
That's wonderful, Deanna.
She mentioned how much
she was looking forward
to seeing you again, Captain.
Did she?
Commander, could I have
a word with you?
Is something wrong, Captain?
Tell me, Number One.
Is the entire crew aware
of this little scheme
to send me off on holiday?
I believe there are two ensigns
stationed on deck 39
who know nothing about it.
I suppose this means
I can look forward to a week
of continual harassment
on this subject?
( sighs )
I admit I have been feeling
a little fatigued.
I'll see to it
that these bags
are beamed directly
to your room, sir.
You look very handsome,
if I might say so, Captain.
Are you taking
all these books?
I thought I'd take
some light reading
in case I got bored.
Ulysses by James Joyce?
Ethics, Sophistry and
the Alternate Universe.
Ving Kuda-- you call
that light reading?
To each his own, Number One.
Have I mentioned
how imaginative
the Risian women
are, sir?
Too often, Commander.
I do have one request, sir.
You want me to bring you back
a souvenir?
It's called a Horga'hn.
I don't think you'll have
any trouble finding one.
Consider it done.
Captain, I would feel better
if you would allow me
to assign a security
officer to you.
We will be out of communication
range when we leave orbit.
( sighs )
I really don't think that will
be necessary, Mr. Worf.
Risa has a reputation
of being a most peaceful planet.
Aye, sir.
Well, the ship is yours,
Number One.
Enjoy your
trip, Captain.
I'll try, Counselor.
He's going to have
a great time.
( people talking, laughing )
( birds singing )
Oh... I beg your pardon.
God, it's so good
to see you again.
I think you've mistaken me
for someone else.
You know, I think
you might be right.
Welcome to Risa.
A simple handshake
would have sufficed.
( woman laughing )
( women squealing
with laughter )
( people talking, laughing )
( sighs )
( ball humming )
( humming )
WOMAN:
Return.
My apologies.
I fear I have yet to master
the art of hoverball.
So it would seem.
My name is Joval.
I'm employed here.
Is there anything
you require
to make your stay
a more pleasant one?
You find me amusing.
No.
It's just that you are
the fifth woman
to ask me that question
this morning.
All I require is to sit
in the sun, read my book...
alone.
And afterward?
I really hadn't thought
that far ahead.
Then, may I suggest a swim,
followed by a massage.
Some other time, perhaps.
I don't understand.
You say you wish
to be alone
yet, you carry the Horga'hn.
Well, I just purchased it.
Why?
Are you implying this has
some special meaning?
The Horga'hn is the Risian
symbol of sexuality.
To own one
is to call forth its powers.
To display it is to announce
you are seeking jamaharon.
Riker.
Do you seek jamaharon?
I don't even know what it means.
The Horga'hn is for a friend.
I see.
Someone close to you.
That's right.
Someone you love.
I wouldn't go that far.
Well, your attitude
is most puzzling.
I will leave you
now to your book.
That is all I ask.
You're blocking the suns.
I know you're working with her.
I warn you, it's a mistake.
Are you addressing me?
Don't bother to deny it.
I've seen the two
of you together.
I don't know what the devil
you're talking about.
But, whatever it is, I assure
you, it's no concern of mine.
Tell her I want the disk
returned to me immediately.
Perhaps I have not
made myself clear.
You have the wrong man.
I am rapidly losing patience
with you.
I demand you
talk business.
You'll find Ferengi demands
carry little weight with me.
Obviously, you've never dealt
with my people before.
( chuckles )
On the contrary.
All too often.
Then, you know the Ferengi
are not to be trifled with.
Or trusted.
You dare to insult me?!
I advise you to listen closely,
for I will not say this again.
I came to Risa for a holiday,
nothing more.
I have no knowledge
of this woman of whom you speak
nor have I set eyes on any disk.
( laughs )
You expect me
to believe such
feeble lies?
I don't care what you believe!
This is not
over yet, human.
The disk is mine!
And so is the woman.
Remember that.
WOMAN:
Hello.
Oh, it's you.
Well, that's not much
of a greeting.
Look, I don't wish
to appear rude
but I am not seeking
jamaharon.
All right.
But you really should try it
sometime.
If I try it
it will be
at a time
of my own choosing.
That's fine with me.
It's not as though I was
offering to help you find it.
Uh... I, uh...
I assumed that
because of the way you
welcomed me the other day...
I'm sorry
if I embarrassed you.
I don't recall
saying I was embarrassed.
It's just that I prefer
to be acquainted
with the women that I kiss.
That's understandable.
The name's Vash.
Jean-Luc Picard.
So tell me about yourself,
Jean-Luc.
( sighs heavily )
Would you rather I guess?
I can be
very persistent.
I'm the Captain
of a Federation starship.
Oh...
That explains it.
Explains what?
I noticed you arguing
with that Ferengi.
For a moment there
it looked like it was going
to come to blows.
You're the woman
he was talking about.
I hope your disagreement
wasn't over me.
For that information,
you'll have to ask him.
Where are you going?
To find some privacy.
Wait a second.
What did he tell you?
I bet there wasn't
a bit of truth to it.
And you said you
didn't know her.
I don't.
And I don't want to.
Return the disk to me
and all will be forgiven.
The disk doesn't belong
to you, Sovak-- it never did.
It would seem the two of you
have a lot to discuss.
If you will excuse me.
Jean-Luc, I'm sorry.
Perhaps I could explain
all this to you later?
Perhaps you can.
I have a proposal
I believe you'll find
most interesting.
Save your breath.
I'm willing to pay you
your weight in gold
in exchange for the disk.
Is that not a generous offer?
Oh... I must have that woman.
What the hell
are you doing in my room?
We are Vorgons.
I am Ajur.
This is Boratus.
We come from
the 27th century.
We traveled 300
years into the past
to find you.
All right, let's assume for the
moment that I believe you.
That you are, indeed,
from the future.
What is it
you want from me?
Have you heard of the Tox Uthat?
What?
I'm aware of the legend.
It tells of a visitor...
from the future
who left behind a mysterious
device known as the Tox Uthat.
Essentially that story
is correct.
Then the Uthat actually exists?
Yes. It was invented by
a scientist named Kal Dano
in the mid-27th century.
The Uthat is a quantum
phase inhibitor
capable of halting all
nuclear reaction within a star.
But... why bring such
a powerful weapon into the past?
Criminals attempted
to steal the device
so he fled back
to the 22nd century,
where he hid it.
Ajur and I were
the security team
assigned to
retrieve the Uthat.
I gather you were unsuccessful.
Yes.
When we returned
we began to search
through the historical records
for some clue
to the Uthat's fate.
And your search led you to me?
We came upon a brief account
stating that you had discovered
an object of unknown origin
while vacationing in Risa.
From its description--
a crystal fitting
into the palm of the hand--
we surmised it could
very well be the Tox Uthat.
Well, I'm sorry
to disappoint you
but I haven't found anything,
including peace
which is the only thing
I'm looking for.
You will find
such a device, Captain.
To us, it is already
part of history.
And, uh, if I find it,
what then?
You will give it to us
immediately
so that we may return with it.
Well, the Uthat belongs
to your time, not mine.
( buzzing whir )
May I come in?
Excuse the mess.
Sovak has taken to searching
my room periodically.
This what he's
looking for?
I'm sorry I had
to hide it like that.
I was afraid he'd start
searching me next.
This disk must contain some
very valuable information.
Well, I doubt it's anything
you'd be interested in.
Depends.
On what?
On whether or not
it has something to do
with the Tox Uthat.
Did Sovak tell you that?
Well, let's
just say
I've heard... rumors
that the Uthat is located
somewhere on Risa.
Look, the last thing I need
is a partner.
So it's true.
Have a seat.
I don't suppose you ever heard
of Professor Samuel Estragon?
Yes, as a matter
of fact, I have.
He spent half his life searching
for the Tox Uthat.
I served
as his personal assistant
for the past five years.
Shortly before he died,
he uncovered new data
pinpointing its location
and that disk contains
his research notes and maps.
And you're continuing his work.
Exactly.
With a Ferengi as an associate?
Sovak and I definitely are not
working together.
But the two
of you
are... very well acquainted.
Well, at times
he aided the professor
in his explorations.
Especially in situations
that weren't quite ethical.
And now with typical
Ferengi logic
he's convinced that
the Tox Uthat belongs to him.
All he cares about is selling it
to the highest bidder.
Whereas you, of course,
have a nobler purpose in mind.
I told the professor
I'd present it
to the Daystrom
Institute for study.
Ah.
But, first, I have
to find it
and that won't be easy with
Sovak watching me every minute.
I'll go in your place.
And what about me?
You remain here.
It's safer.
Is that an order?
Absolutely.
This isn't a starship, Jean-Luc.
I don't follow orders.
Oh, I see.
Besides, you'd never
find it without me.
The professor's notes
are in code.
From the moment I met you
I knew you were going
to be trouble.
You look like a man
who could handle trouble.
So, where exactly
is the location?
It's about 27 kilometers
due east.
There's some subterranean
caves there.
That's where you'll
find the Uthat.
I'll meet you in the lobby
in 15 minutes.
Be punctual.
Oh, and, uh, I advise you
to change your clothing.
Jean-Luc?
We're going to make
a wonderful team.
( people talking, laughing )
( birds singing )
I expected such treachery.
Did you think
you could sneak
away from me
so easily?
The disk-- where is it?
Didn't anyone tell you weapons
aren't allowed on Risa?
You're making a grave mistake
putting your trust
in this woman.
It would be a worse mistake
to trust you.
Silence!
Do you know how she acquired
the disk in the first place?
Sovak!
( laughing )
I paid her to steal it.
But instead,
she betrayed me
and used my money
to make her way here.
It didn't happen that way.
She's a greedy
and unscrupulous woman.
( sighing )
A perfect mate for a Ferengi.
You're becoming quite annoying,
Sovak.
As are you, human.
Perhaps I should kill you
and then take the disk.
No, wait.
You can have it.
See, I told you we'd
make a wonderful team.
We've got a long trip.
( device beeping )
Have you calculated
how much further we have to go?
Another 11 kilometers.
We should stay here
for the night.
I was hoping
you'd say that.
Actually, we've...
we've made better time
than I expected.
Well, I'll take that
as a compliment.
As it was intended.
( sighs )
Jean-Luc...
I'm afraid I haven't been
completely honest with you.
Forgive me
if I don't act surprised.
Sovak did pay me
to hand over the disk.
So you did steal it.
It wasn't stealing.
The professor had died.
I had already spent
five years of my life
tracking down the Uthat.
But you took Sovak's money.
It was the only way
I could afford to get to Risa.
As for Sovak, he got
exactly what he deserved.
Well, any woman who can
beat a Ferengi at his own game
bears watching.
I'll take that
as another compliment.
I'm flattered.
Hmm. Well...
we should get some sleep.
You know, Jean-Luc, it's
lucky for you we met.
If it wasn't for me...
If it wasn't for me
you'd still be back there
sitting in the sun, relaxing.
That happens to be
why I came to Risa.
I'm sure you hated
every minute of it.
That kind of vacation
isn't for a man like you.
You need excitement.
Excitement?
Spending the night
in a damp cave
chasing after something we
shall probably never find?
You're enjoying yourself,
aren't you?
Ah.
Yes.
I just wanted
to hear you say it.
Good, now let's
get some sleep.
( chuckles )
I'll never forget that look
on your face
when you thought I was
offering you jamaharon.
Now, that was a simple
misunderstanding.
Oh.
( sighs )
You did seem
a little disappointed
when I turned you down.
( chuckling )
You are outrageous.
Thank you.
You're pretty stimulating
yourself.
Don't you see?
We're a lot alike.
That's probably why
we get along so well.
You call this
getting along?
Fine.
We don't get along.
We're not getting along.
I didn't say that.
No, no. If you want to believe
that we're not getting along
that's all
right with me...
You still think
I'm trouble?
I'm sure of it.
( device beeping )
VASH:
This is it.
We've reached the end
of our journey.
( beeping )
Do you have the
exact location?
Seven meters from the opening,
along the wall.
That should make it
about here.
( beeping louder )
What the...?!
Is something wrong?
( sighs )
I can't get a reading on this.
There must be Starithium ore
in these rocks.
And that leaves us
but one alternative.
Shall we?
Picard!
A little premature,
aren't we?
We are to be a witness
to a great moment, Picard.
Who the hell are they?
They are...
security officers
from the 27th century.
They're here to take back the
Uthat.
You knew about this
and didn't say anything?
I'm sorry, Vash.
Would you have brought me here
if I had told you?
Probably not.
My point exactly.
SOVAK:
So, the betrayer
is herself betrayed.
Well, you've put together
quite a little team.
Do not interrupt the Captain.
SOVAK:
Quiet!
PICARD:
How did you get here?
SOVAK:
I found the disk in her room.
That's impossible.
I made a copy
as a precaution
but I burned it
before we left.
Ah... only the outer casing
was incinerated.
Now, I had no intention
of interrupting you.
Please, continue digging!
( laughing )
( grunting )
No one told you
to stop digging, human.
I see no reason
to continue.
You will do as I say.
Look about you, Sovak.
By now it must be
obvious, even to you.
The Uthat is not here.
( Sovak cackling )
Is this
some pathetic attempt
at trickery?
Of course, it's here.
We simply haven't
found it yet.
Are you saying that the
professor's findings were wrong?
It would appear so.
But how can that be?
His evidence
was overwhelming.
Enough with this foolishness!
Can't you see
he's trying to deceive us?
Return to work this instant.
I'm afraid he's right, Sovak.
According to the disk, we should
have reached it hours ago.
Lies!
Treachery!
This cannot be happening.
Not another failure.
Not after having come so close.
It is most puzzling.
( buzzing whir )
It's over, Sovak.
No, I will not be cheated
out of my prize.
Tell him!
Tell him the professor's
research is irrefutable.
I don't know anymore.
Then step aside.
The Uthat is here, somewhere.
It's just waiting to be found.
It can't hide
from me forever.
( panting )
Five years of my life wasted.
There will be
other treasures
to be found, Vash.
Not like the Uthat.
I hope you won't mind,
but, um...
I need to be alone.
( birds calling )
RIKER:
Enterprise to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
Go ahead, Commander.
We hope we're not interrupting
anything important, Captain
but we wanted to inform you
that we have achieved orbit
around Risa
and we're ready to beam you
aboard at your convenience.
I'll be returning shortly,
Commander.
In the interim, stand ready
to initiate Transporter Code 14
at my signal.
Transporter Code 14?
You heard me, Number One.
Yes, sir.
Picard out.
PICARD:
Leaving so soon?
Jean-Luc.
I was just about
to come say good-bye.
Well, then... I've
saved you the bother.
I want to put this all behind me
as soon as possible.
You understand?
Of course.
There's just one last
thing you can do for me.
Anything.
Tell me where you've
hidden the Tox Uthat.
That's not funny.
You never intended to
burn that second disk.
If you had, you wouldn't
have been so careless
as to allow Sovak
to salvage any of it.
You wanted him
to follow us
so that he could
see for himself
that the Uthat wasn't
at the cave site.
That was the only way
he could be convinced
that your quest
had been futile.
But how could I have known
the Uthat wasn't there?
Because you had already
been there once before.
Probably the moment you
arrived on the planet.
That's when you found it.
You're a man
of many talents, Jean-Luc.
A piece of the future.
A very dangerous piece.
Were you really
going to give this
to the Daystrom Institute?
Well, maybe not give it.
Five years is
a huge investment, Jean-Luc.
I deserve to make
a reasonable profit.
Congratulations,
Picard.
We knew you
would not fail us.
You're not going to just
hand it over, are you?
You didn't trust me.
What makes you think
you can trust them?
I assume the Vorgons have proof
to back up their claim.
Our being here
is proof enough.
Wait a second, Vorgons?
The professor's notes said
that it was two Vorgons
a male and a female,
who attempted
to steal the Uthat
in the first place.
For all we know,
it could be them.
You, uh... You're going
to have to prove
that you are
who you say you are.
You yourself said
the Uthat belongs
to the future.
But not necessarily to you.
You will return
what is ours.
No!
Enterprise, Code 14.
Lock onto present coordinates,
two-second delay.
Mark!
Are you all right?
Go.
Return
to your own time.
There's nothing for you here.
History recorded
that you destroyed the Uthat.
You have fulfilled
your destiny all
too well, Picard.
( buzzing whir )
I don't suppose
there are any openings
for an archaeologist
aboard the Enterprise.
Somehow I doubt you'd find
life aboard a starship
suitable to your taste.
Probably not.
I could never tolerate
all that discipline.
Oh...
So...
What are your plans?
I thought I might explore
the ruins on Sarthong V.
Oh! Unbelievable!
You are out of your mind.
The Sarthongians are merciless
to trespassers.
Why, Jean-Luc...
you really do care about me.
Promise me you will try
and stay out of trouble.
I always try.
I wish we had more time
together.
Well, perhaps we do.
The Vorgons are time travelers.
Now they know where and when
the Uthat can be found
they may very well come back
and try for it again.
So we may be doing this
all over again.
Welcome aboard, Captain.
Status report,
Number One.
All went well
on Starbase 12.
I think you'll find the ship
in splendid condition.
I'll present my compliments
to the crew.
Oh, yes, Number One
about that Horga'hn
you requested.
Yes, sir?
You and I need to have
a little chat about that.
Was it a relaxing
trip, Captain?
Uh-huh.
I knew he'd have a great time.