PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43779.3:
The Enterprise is preparing
detailed exospheric charts
of the Hayashi system.
Although tedious,
this endeavor is
the first step
toward planet colonization.
Captain, sensors report
the U.S.S. Hood
is closing at
an intercept course
at high warp.
That's odd.
We weren't notified
of a rendezvous.
They seem to be
in an awful hurry.
Sir, we are being hailed
on a secured channel
by Captain Desoto.
On screen.
Sorry to sneak up on you
like that, Jean-Luc.
Robert, why didn't
you inform us?
Out here, you never know
who's listening.
Keeps you on
your toes anyway.
Eh, Will?
Will, you getting soft
on board that luxury liner?
PICARD:
So, old friend
how are you?
Well you know,
they send you
galaxy-class boys
out here to the far reaches.
Me, I just haul my butt
back and forth
between starbases.
But not today.
No, not today.
Starfleet's got
new orders for you.
This is top priority.
They need the fastest ship
in the fleet
and the best people.
That is you.
If time was so important,
why didn't they transmit
the orders by subspace?
Well,
they're worried about
Romulan eavesdropping
on this one.
And we have
a passenger for you.
Kind of hard to send
by subspace.
What sort of passenger?
Mission specialist.
He'll bring your orders
aboard with him.
His name is Tam Elbrun.
As in Tam Elbrun
of the Ghorusda disaster?
The same.
What can I say?
Your orders are to
cooperate fully with him.
Best of luck, folks.
Hood out.
Sir, the Hood is
slowing to impulse.
Mr. Data,
come with me.
Captain, may I come
with you to greet Tam?
You know him?
I do, he was at
the university on Betazed
when I was studying
psychology there.
Oh I see, he was
a colleague of yours.
No... he was a patient.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Tam is a telepath
of extraordinary talent,
even for a Betazoid.
He's a specialist
in first contact
with new life-forms.
He's a very
unique person,
but he's not what you
might expect, Captain.
Welcome aboard
the Enterprise.
I am Captain--
Captain Picard.
Right?
Here.
You want to know
all about your mission.
Everything's on there.
Orders and briefings.
Destination and heading,
all that.
Dee, I sensed
you were out here.
How have you been?
I've been fine,
but I thought...
BOTH:
...you were on Chandra Five?
DATA:
Sir?
Who ... what are you?
I am Data,
an android.
Incredible.
An android.
I can't read you
at all.
It's like
you're not there.
PICARD:
Data.
Oh, you better hurry up
to the bridge with that.
Captain wants you
to run the orders,
scan the technical
schematics,
and be ready to brief him
in ten minutes, right?
Number One?
Riker here.
Will you meet Commander Data
on the bridge?
He has our orders
and new heading.
Aye, sir.
And assemble
the bridge staff
for a mission briefing
in 15 minutes.
Picard out.
Mister Elbrun,
would you..?
Would I care
to see my quarters?
No.
I'd rather get
this briefing over with,
then be left alone
until I'm needed.
I've heard something
about Ghorusda.
Weren't there about
40 people killed?
47, including the Captain
of the Adelphi,
two friends from my
class at the academy.
Hmm, sorry.
Main bridge.
So what happened?
It was a first-contact
situation.
Ghorusdan culture is
so complex and different
that the federation
sent a specialist
to prevent
misunderstanding.
So that was Tam Elbrun.
What happened
was his fault?
Not directly.
Board of inquiry
blamed Darson
for carelessness
about Ghorusdan
cultural taboos.
But if Elbrun was so good,
why didn't he warn Darson?
What was he doing there
if he couldn't sense
that much hostility?
Our destination is
the Beta Stromgren system
following the path
of the Vega Nine probe.
That's 23 parsecs beyond our
furthest manned explorations.
That is correct,
Commander.
Apparently the probe has
discovered...
astonishing.
Our orders are to proceed
to this star, Beta Stromgren.
Scientists have discovered
it is in the final stages
of an alternating cycle
of expansion and collapse
and will soon result
in a supernova.
However, the unmanned,
long ranged space probe
sent by Starfleet
to observe the process
has discovered
something much more.
Oh, oh, Data,
don't waste time.
They call it "Tin Man".
The Vega probe found it
orbiting Stromgren.
Looks like
some kind of ship.
Its energy source
is unknown.
The people who have studied
the transmissions
think it's a starship.
And they're sure
it's alive.
Alive? How?
A cybernetic organism,
like the Borg?
No, no, no.
Here.
Starfleet believes
it's an organic creature
born in space,
living its life
in the wastes
between the stars.
No one knows
where it came from
or why it's here.
But we're going
to meet it.
We're going to talk to it.
I'm going to talk to it.
Have attempts been made...
To communicate
with it by subspace?
Of course,
linguacode,
universal translation,
all that, it won't work.
Tin Man is too different.
Direct mind-to-mind contact
is our only hope.
The opportunity for discovery
is extraordinary,
but I don't understand
Starfleet's urgency.
Romulans.
Oh, hell, I forgot.
The Romulans.
They claim
that sector of space
where Beta Stromgren
is located.
The Romulans claim all that
is in their field of vision.
They routinely monitor
the telemetry of
our deep space probes.
And they will certainly be
sending a ship of their own
to investigate
this "Tin Man."
No.
Actually,
they're sending two.
Data?
That is correct.
Starbase 123 has detected
two D'deridex-class cruisers
on an intercept course.
The top speed
of this class cruiser
is known to be
less than ours.
Therefore, we do have
some advantage.
Then it's a race.
An alien intelligence,
a new life-form
representing a technology
far beyond either the Romulans
or ourselves.
The Romulans will certainly take
whatever measures are required
to secure
this creature for study.
Study as in
"dissecting," I'd bet.
Mr. Data,
you are our resident
honor student
in exobiology.
I'm assigning you to head up the
life sciences on this mission.
Aye, sir.
Excellent.
Meeting adjourned, then.
So, Data,
I guess you're the brains
of this outfit, huh?
Mr. Elbrun, one of the reasons
I'm asking you to work closely
with a member of my staff
is to avoid...
further omissions.
The possibility
of an encounter
with the Romulans
on this mission
is hardly trivial,
and yet....
All right, all right.
I should have brought up
the Romulans earlier,
but I was distracted.
And no, Billy Boy,
I wasn't distracted
on Ghorusda.
If Darson had listened to me,
no one would have died.
No?
Well, I don't care whether
you believe that or not.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
Traveling at high warp,
we are still
several days from rendezvous
with the mysterious entity
which Starfleet has
christened "Tin Man."
My immediate concern is
with Tam Elbrun.
Starfleet considers
his unique abilities
crucial to our mission,
yet he seems to me
unstable.
Well, according to his medical
records and psych profile,
he's very high
on the E.S.P. scale.
A sort of prodigy.
A prodigy?
In what sense?
Well, in most Betazoids,
our telepathic gifts
develop at adolescence.
You mean you're not
born reading minds?
No, except for some reason
that no one understands,
occasionally a Betazoid child
is born different.
How different?
Born with its telepathic
abilities switched on.
Most Betazoids born like that
never lead a normal life.
The noise of other people's
thoughts and feelings
must be overwhelming,
incomprehensible,
especially to a child.
And painful.
Early diagnosis
and special training
did help Tam adjust,
but he has
some problems.
You mentioned
a hospitalization.
For stress-- repeatedly,
throughout his life.
I always wonder
what holds one person together
through that
kind of struggle
while another
goes under?
Yes, well,
he's evidently done more
than "hold together."
He's the indispensable man--
the Federation's finest
specialist in communication
with unknown life-forms.
The more unusual
the life-form,
the better he likes it.
His personnel file shows
he's gravitated towards
assignments that isolate him
from other humanoids.
Commander Data,
I'm picking up an unusual echo
on my navigational
sensors.
Something is
out there, sir,
tracking us, matching
our speed and heading.
Something which does
not fully register
on our instruments.
Since there is
no known natural phenomenon
capable of travel
at warp velocity,
there are but
two possibilities.
Either it is a sensor
malfunction,
or another ship is
following us covertly.
It is not
a sensor malfunction.
Agreed.
WESLEY:
But, Commander,
if it is a Romulan ship,
with their cloaking device,
we shouldn't
pick them up at all.
Unless they're pulling so much
power for something else
that they can't
fully cloak.
Like what?
Ask the Romulans...
if it is the Romulans.
DATA:
Lieutenant,
continue monitoring
the precise position
of the echo.
Any sudden change
in its behavior,
initiate yellow alert.
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Come in.
How are things
in the land of the living?
I thought
you might be lonely.
No one sees you
except Data.
Lonely?
I can hear everything that
everyone on this ship thinks,
and no one besides you
seems to be missing
my charming...
You want them
to dislike you.
Why?
Because I'm not
a nice man.
Okay, okay.
Because they scare me.
There are
too many minds.
I can't shut them out.
Never could learn.
All their loves,
their hates,
their fears,
their needs.
It's like a tide
that never ebbs.
I could drown.
I remember.
You understood,
at least a little,
how I felt.
I see you finally found
a place to fit in,
people to care about.
And you're
still looking.
And then
there's Ghorusda.
I have enough doubt
in my reliability
without having to listen
to Riker's and Picard's.
What happened there?
I thought everyone knew.
No. What happened to you?
Maybe I got too involved
with the Ghorusdans,
with their point of view.
It happens to me.
I wanted everyone
to get along.
I could have warned Darson
more forcefully.
So, after that,
you ran away.
The last I heard,
you were the only
Federation delegate
assigned
to Chandra Five.
Oh, beautiful creatures,
the Chandrans.
Their minds are glacial.
They have a lovely
three-day ritual
for saying "hello."
Peaceful,
untroubled people.
Unlike humanoids?
Well, except for
your friend, Data.
I like him.
He's... restful.
I believe your impression
of Data is probably unique.
Yeah?
Well, having to get
to know someone,
just once,
has its appeal.
I mean,
talking to them
instead of getting it
all at once, up here,
whether I want it or not.
But you accepted
this mission.
You could have stayed
on Chandra Five.
You willingly
came aboard a ship
with over
a thousand people.
How could I not?
Think of it, Dee.
This intelligence that
swims naked through space
like a fish in the sea,
totally alien,
mysterious,
not like us at all.
Ancient...
and alone.
So lonely...
for so long.
How can you know that?
Tam?
You're in contact
with it.
With Tin Man,
aren't you?
No.
Well...
yes, a little,
but not quite
on a conscious level.
We're light-years away.
That's impossible,
even for you.
Impossible for me.
Maybe not impossible
for Tin Man.
Status report,
Number One?
We've reached the outer regions
of the Beta Stromgren system,
on course for
orbital intercept
with the Tin Man,
E.T.A 18 minutes.
Grand.
Not altogether.
Astrophysics reports
that the rate of
the star's collapse
has increased.
It could go supernova
in a few days.
DATA:
Captain, we are receiving
relay sensor data
from the Vega probe
including visuals.
On screen.
Magnify.
Remarkable.
Computer,
locate Tam Elbrun.
COMPUTER:
Tam Elbrun is in turbolift one
en route
to the main bridge.
Of course.
WORF: Captain,
our sensors are detecting
a subspace wave front
of highly ionized particles
preceding the object
which is tracking us.
Yellow alert.
On screen.
Romulan warbird closing.
They are arming
main disruptors, captain.
Order red alert.
Shields to maximum.
Arm photon torpedoes
and stand by, Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
I thought you said
the Enterprise
was faster than
this Romulan.
In fact, we are,
Commander, however...
Evasive, Mr. Crusher.
Hailing frequencies.
I guarantee that they don't
want to talk to you, Captain.
WORF:
The Romulan has passed us.
Damage report.
No casualties reported.
70 percent loss
to the shields.
Their attack on us was
incidental, Captain.
Incidental?
Yes, to delay us.
Captain, it would appear
the Romulans intent is
to contact "Tin Man" first,
at any cost.
According to my
sensor readings,
the Warbird has exceeded
maximum engine output by 30%.
They seem to have irreparable
damage to their warp coils.
So they kept up with us
by sacrificing their ability
to re-enter
Romulan space.
A one-way trip.
There's one more
trailing us, Captain.
A day or two behind.
Data's right,
this one's job...
is to beat us
to Tin Man at any cost.
You read all this
telepathically?
In the mind of
the Romulan commander,
during the attack.
Very well,
Mr. Crusher, all stop.
Aye, sir.
Commander La Forge?
La forge here.
Geordi, how long
to full shield restoration?
I'm working on it.
Computer, reconfigure
structural integrity power
to feed inner
deflector grid.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Requested reroute
would compromise
operational
safety limits.
To hell with
the limits, override.
Authorization,
La Forge, Theta 2997.
COMPUTER:
Rerouting structural integrity
power supply.
Russell, watch
the lateral grid balance.
No-no-no,
that's too much.
We'll have to do it
manually.
La Forge to bridge.
PICARD:
Go ahead.
Captain, I'm trying
to feed the inner grid
by stealing some power from
the structural integrity field.
You should have partial
shielding in about 30 minutes.
PICARD:
You have ten.
Picard out.
The Romulans wish
the honor of first contact.
Let them have it.
You're out of
your mind, Picard.
What if the Romulans find
a way to persuade Tin Man...
I think the chance
of that is remote.
And if you will be
still, Mr. Elbrun,
you may learn...
What?
That being first
at any cost
is not always
the point.
Mr. Data,
while we await repairs,
I want life sciences
and engineering
to continue collecting
information on the alien.
And query the Vega Nine probe,
long-range sensors.
Aye, sir.
You do a lot
of your work here?
Yes.
I have configured
these instruments
to display information with
greater speed and efficiency
than stations
used by the others.
Nice.
A little spartan.
Spartan?
Lots of work space.
Not much room to live.
I don't guess you sleep.
I have tried it
from time to time,
but you are correct.
I do not
require rest.
But you paint.
The creature's anatomy
appears most peculiar.
In what way?
It is indeed
laid out as a vessel
with what appear to be
chambers and corridors.
An internal environment
suitable for
carbon-based life-forms
is being maintained,
yet...
there is no evidence
of a crew aboard.
Tin Man is
a living being
which has been bred
or has adapted itself
to serve a purpose.
I find that
interesting.
Why?
Must living beings
have a purpose?
Or do we exist for
no reason but to exist?
I do not believe I am qualified
to express an opinion.
Ah, Data, you're
uniquely qualified.
You think a great deal
about humanity,
and you're
an honest researcher.
You don't treat anything
as trivial or irrelevant.
You want to try it all.
You said in
the transporter room
that you could not
read my mind.
True enough.
But I think I understand
you pretty well.
It worries you
that I can't read your mind?
Perhaps there is
nothing to read.
Nothing more than mechanisms
and algorithmic responses.
Perhaps you're
just different.
It's not a sin,
you know.
Though you may have
heard otherwise.
Captain, the Romulan ship
is hailing the alien
using their equivalent
of linguacode.
Response?
DATA:
Nothing so far,
Commander.
TAM:
Why should it answer?
What could it possibly have
in common with them?
But you're so sure
it'll talk to you?
Captain, the Romulans are
arming all disruptors.
Yellow alert.
Prepare for evasive action
of the first change
in the Romulans' course.
RIKER: With our shields
in this position, we can't...
No, no...
we're not the target.
It's Tin Man.
What do you mean?
Do they intend
to destroy it?
Those are their orders
if they can't secure the alien.
Increase speed to intercept
the Romulan vessel.
Their lead is
too great, sir.
Hail them.
We can not allow them...
They won't listen
to you!
Danger.
Gomtuu... do not allow.
Damage report!
WORF:
Nothing available yet, sir.
We have partial failure
of the main computer.
It seems you woke...
your Tin Man.
We've got impulse power,
but I've got to take
the warp engines offline
while we recalibrate
the intermix regulators.
How long?
For everything
or just for
the warp engines?
All of it.
Commander, we're looking
at 20 hours work here,
double shifts.
We don't know that
we have 20 hours.
That star could
explode at any moment.
I know.
Okay, first thing
we need to do is
get the main computer
working right--
No, we fix
the shields first--
Commander, whatever
Tin Man hit us with,
it fried circuits
I thought were unfryable.
I'm not worried
about Tin Man.
It's more Romulans
showing up.
Right. First priority,
get the shields up.
Only, let's not have anymore
surprises until I'm done, okay?
Don't ask me
about surprises.
Ask Tam Elbrun.
Your brain activity
suggests you're coming out
of some sort
of a fugue or seizure.
Your blood pressure
and glucose are indicative
of general
systemic stress.
But I'm gonna live?
No doubt about it.
Good.
Because I want to know
exactly what you did.
I want to know how closely
you're in communication
with this alien
and what you've learned from it.
And I want to know now!
I... I...
I just warned it,
that's all.
I've been
in contact with it,
sensing impressions
from it.
It calls itself Gomtuu.
It's old, Captain.
It's roamed the universe
for many thousands of years.
Where did it come from?
How many...
Far away.
Maybe beyond
the galaxy.
Once, there were
millions of them.
Once?
It hasn't seen another
of its kind for millennia.
It's alone.
It may be the last
of its species.
Perhaps...
we can help it
in some way.
Can you ask it
to return with us
to Federation space?
At least persuade it
to leave the vicinity
of Beta Stromgren
before the star explodes?
Captain, Gomtuu knows
the star will go nova soon.
That's why it's here.
It wants to die.
There was...
an explosion in space.
Radiation penetrating
the outer layers.
The crew...
( heavy sighing )
the crew...
died.
Such loss...
empty pain...
hollowness...
Tam, stop this.
You're losing yourself
in this merging.
I know, I know.
Tin Man hurts
and wants to die.
I can't do any more
from out here.
If you want me
to really reach Tin Man,
I have got to be
in physical contact.
I have got
to go aboard.
No that is absolutely
out of the question.
You don't trust me?
No, Tam, I don't
believe that I do.
Tam...
when you reached out
to the alien to warn it,
did you give any thought
to this vessel?
To the danger,
however inadvertent,
that creature might
pose to our crew,
or did you simply
react out of instinct?
Captain...
Deanna...
he's right.
I don't know,
I don't know
what might happen,
but if you don't let me go,
we fail our mission.
Besides,
at this point,
you need all the help
you can get,
even Tin Man's.
Russell, reactivate
the sensor assemblies.
Okay.
Let's do a program reload,
port array only.
Good, that's good.
Computer, run
a level-two diagnostic.
COMPUTER:
Port sensor array
remains off-line.
Damn!
RIKER:
Riker to La Forge.
How's it coming?
Not good.
I think all the control
processes are shot.
But maybe if I swap the chips
from the secondary array,
I can give you
a minimum E.M. scan.
RIKER:
Do it.
Okay, Russell,
we're going to try
starting retro sensor
element 32 only.
You in?
Go.
( whistles )
The good news is we have
partial long range sensors.
La Forge to Bridge.
Riker here.
I'm picking up another echo on
the long range sensor display.
You reading that on your panel?
Worf?
One moment, Commander.
Confirmed.
Sir, the other Romulan ship
on an intercept course.
Geordi, are we gonna have
those shields anytime soon?
GEORDI:
I'm doing the best I can.
But shields won't help
if that star explodes.
Data, you seem to have developed
an affinity with Elbrun.
Troi, you've
known him for years.
How far can he be trusted?
Captain, the issue
isn't one of trust
in Tam's intentions
but in his judgment.
I would trust him to do
what he believes is right.
Yes, of course,
but his judgment...
Is precarious.
The stress of exposure
to so many minds
on the ship is bad enough.
Now he's strongly drawn
to this creature.
I'm afraid for him.
Afraid of what?
I sense that the alien
is somehow calling him.
If we allow him
to do as he insists--
to beam over--
I believe that we will
lose him to it.
That he will
lose himself.
Captain, I agree that
Tam's motives are trustworthy.
And I do not believe
it is possible
that he will
act against us
or will cause Tin Man to act
against us out of malice.
Captain, if Tam
breaks down over there,
we'll be no closer
to accomplishing our mission.
It will be
a grave mistake.
Thank you both.
Data?
I am puzzled, sir.
We have come this far.
Are you not going to allow Tam
to fulfill his mission?
Tam Elbrun warned Tin Man.
The first thing it did
was to destroy a space vessel.
I believe
I understand, sir.
If you feel the risk
is too great
to send Tam Elbrun alone,
then send me with him.
Counselor Troi
understands him better.
But he is more
comfortable with me, sir.
It is humanity
he is fleeing.
Sir, I could serve
as an intermediary-
a bridge back.
A reminder of
his obligation
both to us
and to Tin Man.
Captain, the Romulan
has uncloaked.
Status, Number One?
Shields are at 40%.
We can maneuver
on impulse, sir.
WORF:
Phasers available
on manual, sir.
Computer target lock
not functioning.
Well, let's hope
they're in a mood to talk.
Hailing frequencies.
Open.
Romulan vessel,
this is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
Enterprise,
your presence here is
a violation of Romulan space.
You will leave immediately.
We are not familiar
with the terms of your claim
on this sector.
We are here engaged
in scientific research.
Do you wish to participate?
We have monitored the
destruction of our sister ship
by the star creature.
We claim right of vengeance.
We will destroy the alien.
If you interfere,
we will destroy you as well.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
A confrontation between
the Romulan warbird
and Tin Man is imminent.
I have no alternative
but to rely on the telepathic
abilities of Tam Elbrun.
Picard to Tam Elbrun.
TAM: Captain.
Report to Transporter
Room Six immediately.
Captain, I don't...
Commander Data
will meet you there.
TAM: Yes, Captain.
Counselor, we no longer
have a choice.
No, no! Too much! Too much!
Tam?
I can't.
Data to Enterprise.
Enterprise, come in.
No, no, don't.
If it is harming you,
we must return.
Enterprise, respond.
No, it's all right now,
it's all right.
Gomtuu is trying to communicate
a lifetime of experiences to me
in a few seconds.
But I'm all right now.
O'Brien to Bridge.
PICARD: Go ahead, Chief.
I've lost the transporter
lock on them.
Some kind of
force field went up.
Confirmed, the alien
has thrown up a shield.
It is blocking
all our sensors.
Captain.
The Romulans'
weapons systems
are now at full power.
PICARD:
Follow them in, Mr. Crusher.
Red alert.
Mr. Worf, arm photon torpedoes.
Aye, sir.
Yes.
There is a large chamber
20 meters ahead.
I know.
I know everything now.
Come on.
Intriguing.
This is the
control center,
where Gomtuu's crew
guided their journeys.
The ship and the crew
existed symbiotically.
They needed one another.
When Gomtuu had
no one left to care for,
it no longer had
a reason to exist.
Is that the purpose
of existence?
To care for someone?
It is for me.
Deanna was right.
I'll lose myself here.
I must remind you
that our objective
is to bring Tin Man
out of danger
and report our findings
to Starfleet.
I'm not going back, Data.
I'm staying here.
WORF:
Sir, the Romulans
are hailing us.
Captain Picard,
if you interfere with us,
we will fire
upon you as well.
Commander, we are prepared to
defend the life of the alien.
Screen off.
Shields up.
Power levels aboard
the alien are increasing, sir.
Captain, the diameter of
the star has been decreased
by 100,000 kilometers.
It's beginning.
Explain to them.
Make them understand.
But our mission...
Is to save Tin Man.
And I will, but he's going
to save me as well.
All my life,
I have waited for this--
a chance to find peace.
Finally,
all the voices are silent.
Only Tin Man speaks to me now.
Don't you see, Data?
This is where I belong.
That star is going to go
any minute, sir.
The Romulans know that
as well as we do.
Power levels aboard
Tin Man are increasing
beyond our sensor range.
Conn, report.
Dead stop, Captain.
Sir, we've been thrown
clear of Beta Stromgren,
a distance of
3.8 billion kilometers.
There is no sign of Tin Man
or the Romulans, sir.
Captain, on screen.
Data...
DATA:
Sir?
Data, what happened
over there?
Difficult to explain, sir.
Tam?
I believe he found what
he was looking for, Counselor.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
With all main systems
at least temporarily restored,
we are proceeding
to Starbase 152
for inspection
and additional repairs.
We have had no further
encounters with the Romulans.
As for the whereabouts
of Tin Man and Tam Elbrun,
we can only speculate.
You sent for me?
Yes, Counselor.
It was Tam's final request
that I explain
his decision to the crew,
but I believe it was his hope
that you would understand.
What did happen?
I witnessed something...
remarkable.
Individually,
they were both so...
Wounded.
Isolated.
Yes.
But no longer.
Through joining,
they have been healed.
Grief has been
transmuted to joy.
Loneliness to belonging.
Data, you do understand.
Yes, Counselor.
When Tin Man returned me
to the Enterprise,
I realized this
is where I belong.