I don't want any
trouble here, Barclay.
Trouble?
Why would there be trouble?
Because wherever you
go, trouble follows.
Lieutenant Barclay,
you're on duty.
Is that a fact?
It is, and you'll observe it.
So get back
to your post.
Look, pal,
why don't you do me a favor.
Take yourself and your
holier-than-thou attitude
and get out of my life.
This is insubordination,
Mr. Barclay.
Here's to insubordination.
Riker, you're nothing
but a pretty mannequin
in a fancy uniform.
You're full
of hot air.
If Picard has
a problem with me
you tell him to come
and talk to me himself.
I feel your confidence,
your arrogant resolve.
It excites me.
CREWMAN:
Lieutenant Barclay,
report to cargo bay five now.
It'll have to wait
till later, darling.
( loudly ):
Be right there.
Save program.
I just don't know
what to do with him.
The guy's always late.
He never gives
his best effort.
Just slides by.
I'm telling you,
I can't deal with it anymore.
I mean, how does a guy like that
make it through the academy?
I think it's time we
spoke to the captain
about Broccoli.
That's what Wesley
calls him.
You keep that
to yourself.
Well, it fits.
Commander, a broken seal.
Well, you better
destroy it.
Those samples
will be tainted.
LA FORGE:
Hey!
Is it a problem for you
to report to duty
on time, Lieutenant?
No... no, sir.
I'm ... I'm very,
very sorry, sir.
It's just that I had a...
a very important communiqué,
which required
my immediate response.
I don't want to hear it.
Now, we're having
an intermittent problem
with this antigrav unit.
I want you to see
what you can do.
Mr. Barclay, I'm tired
of seeing
your name on report.
I don't know
what you got away with
at your last posting,
but this is the Enterprise.
We set a different
standard here.
Understood?
Understood, sir.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Captain's log,
Stardate 43807.4.
We're taking on a load
of special tissue samples
donated by the Mikulaks for
shipment to Nahmi IV.
The samples could prove
vital to the containment
of an outbreak of correllium
fever on that world.
Everything...
everything looks...
looks normal to me.
Mm-hmm.
LA FORGE:
Computer, activate
antigrav unit.
Damn it.
I... I don't understand.
La Forge to engineering.
I'll need more people
in cargo bay five.
Anyone you can spare.
La Forge out.
We could use a hand,
Mr. Barclay.
Uh, I'll disassemble it
later, Commander.
It shouldn't do that.
Well, I mean... I mean, of
course, it shouldn't do that.
Uh, well, I... I mean...
it shouldn't do that.
I'm just not accustomed
to seeing
an unsatisfactory rating
on a member of my crew.
I guess the question
is whether Mr. Barclay
is Enterprise material.
And I assume
by your request for his transfer
that you think he's not,
Commander.
Well, I hate to say it, but...
I always thought
I could work with anybody
but I just don't
understand this guy.
Broccoli makes me nervous,
Captain.
He makes
everybody nervous.
Broccoli?
Young Mr. Crusher started that.
I guess it's caught on.
Let's just get that
"uncaught," shall we?
There's every
indication that he's
served competently
in Starfleet for years.
Ratings aboard the Zhukov
were satisfactory.
In fact, I recall
Captain Gleason
speaking quite highly of him
before his transfer.
In retrospect, I wonder
if Captain Gleason wasn't
buttering our bread a little.
He knew that we needed
a diagnostic engineer.
I've examined Barclay's
psychological profile.
He has a history
of seclusive tendencies.
It was noted at the academy
more than once.
And yet,
he chose this way of life.
He has made the same commitment
to Starfleet that we all have.
( sighs )
It's easy to transfer a problem
to someone else.
Too easy.
Captain, it's not
like I haven't tried.
Try harder, Geordi.
He's a member of your team.
Try to find some way
to help him to make
a positive contribution.
Get to know the man better.
Make him
your best friend.
With all due respect, sir,
"my best friend"?
I can barely tolerate being
in the same room with the man.
I suggest you put
your personal discomfort
on one side, Commander.
Dismissed.
Yes, sir.
( sighs )
Hey, Reg.
How, uh...
how's it going?
Oh, uh, it's...
I... I still
haven't traced down
the problem, Commander.
It's all right.
There's no problem.
I've... I've been planning
to run diagnostics
on the graviton
inverter's circuits.
Smart plan.
I'd say we're
in good hands here.
Well, I'll see you get
a preliminary report...
Whenever.
Before the end of the day.
Fine. Fine.
Oh... say, Reg,
how about sitting in
on the mission briefing
with my senior officers
in the morning?
Th-the briefing? Me?
I'd like your input.
What on?
I mean, do...
do you want me to prepare...
No, no, just be there.
0800 hours.
I'll... I'll be on time, sir.
Good. Good.
Carry on.
Morning.
Start your brains,
gentlemen
and let's do it.
Has anybody seen
Lieutenant Barclay?
Not yet, sir.
( sighs )
Okay.
( panting )
This trip to Nahmi IV
is pretty routine
so we'll have plenty of time to
realign the magnetic capacitors
of both the matter and
anti-matter injectors.
Duffy, Costa, that'll
be your assignment.
We probably ought to do
the flow regulator maintenance
at the same time, Commander.
That's a good idea.
Ensign Crusher will be
putting in some hours
with us this week
as part of his
training duties.
So, I'll be assigning
him to assist you, Mr. Myers.
Be sure and teach
him the difference
between impulse and
warp drive, please.
( chuckling )
Lieutenant Barclay has been
working on the mystery
of the antigrav failure
we had yesterday.
Your preliminary report
had a couple of interesting
theories, Reg.
Why don't you
bring us all up to speed
on your findings so far.
Yes.
It... it wasn't
a maintenance problem.
Every-everything
checked out.
I'm... I'm going to
look for a surge in
the transfer coils...
Oh, a coil surge
wouldn't have resulted
in field dissipation.
I-I... I realize that.
But we shouldn't ignore
the possibilities, Wes.
You ought to check
the flow capacitor.
A breakdown of that
could have caused
a chain collapse
of the antigrav fields.
I... I was going to.
Good.
Okay, then, let's, uh...
take a look
at that realignment procedure.
Gentlemen.
DUFFY:
Yeah, the bipolar
flux device was...
COSTA:
Commander...
I just didn't know what to say.
What do you wish
you had said?
I should have told him
to mind his own damn business.
I knew about
the flux capacitor
but I didn't need to
hear about it
from some
17-year-old kid.
You're letting this
get you much too upset.
You think so?
Why are you so
hard on yourself?
You don't know.
It's hard out there.
I understand,
but let go of it.
You're here now.
You're right, of course.
Of course.
Let me help you relax.
I'd like that.
I knew you would.
Mmm, that's nice...
But... I'm in the mood
for someplace
a little more...
unusual.
Computer,
run Barclay program 15.
I am the goddess of empathy.
Cast off your inhibitions
and embrace love,
truth, joy.
But I thought that's
the point of the briefing--
to discuss
different approaches...
It's not that you did
anything wrong, Wes.
It's just that Barclay's...
Well, he's my new project.
Yeah, Broccoli's a real project,
all right.
I just need to draw him out
some more.
And I shut him down.
Poor Broccoli.
Pardon me.
But why is Lieutenant Barclay
being referred to
clandestinely
as a vegetable?
It's a joke, Data.
You know, a nickname?
Nicknames generally denote
fondness.
A diminutive shared
between friends.
Data's absolutely right.
The nickname stops here and now.
Captain's orders.
What..? What the hell..?
What happened to your glass?
( tricorder beeping )
Nucleosynthesis.
The structure of the glass
has been altered
at the atomic level.
Problem with
the replicator?
Unlikely.
A problem
with the replicator
would have effected
the contents
as well as the glass
but the liquid in the glass
was a synthehol replication
of a light ale of earth origin
which is, I believe,
what Lieutenant Duffy ordered.
Well, I can't detect
any residual radiation
or any unusual
chemical compounds
that would have
caused this.
The most probable explanation
is that the glass
came into contact
with an unshielded
power source.
Ugh... that means a complete
diagnostic check
of the Enterprise
power systems--
all 4,000 of them.
But do I have the
perfect man for the job.
Hey, Reg.
You busy?
I-I was just...
Uh, no.
Not really.
Why?
Got another mystery for you.
Somehow the molecular structure
of this cup from Ten-Forward
has been altered.
We need to run
through the power systems
to see if there's a leak
that caused this.
I had, uh...
I was going to do that.
You were?
Yes, to try to explain
the antigrav unit failure.
I still can't.
Nothing about it makes sense.
Then it is possible that these
two very disparate incidents
could be related.
I wouldn't bother you with
something this minor, Commander
but it may be a symptom
of a more serious problem.
Do you think we'll need
to put in to a starbase?
We'll have a better idea
after Mr. Barclay runs a check
on the power systems.
It was Lieutenant Barclay
who first suggested
a link between
the two incidents.
What?
No, it wasn't.
I mean, not really.
Will your investigation
affect our available power
during the mission?
No... no, sir.
We'll have to shut off
some systems.
We'll, uh... shut them
down a few at a time.
It shouldn't...
I don't think so.
Good.
I'll look forward
to your report, Mr. Broccoli.
Barclay.
If you will excuse me.
Metathesis is one
of the most common
of pronunciation
errors, sir.
A reversal of vowel
and consonant.
"Barc" to "Broc"...
Yes, I know him.
He comes in.
He stands at the bar.
He doesn't say much.
He orders a warm milk.
( chuckles ):
Figures.
Warm milk helps you sleep,
La Forge.
You should try it.
What's this have to do
with Barclay?
I don't know.
I'm just trying
to figure the man out.
Do you ever talk to him?
He doesn't talk much.
Does he have
any friends?
Not that I've seen.
( sighs )
What do you do
with a guy like that?
Well, I just serve
him warm milk
and let him be.
Yeah, well,
I'm not so lucky.
I can't let him be.
He's my problem.
Hmm.
Well, he's...
imaginative.
How do you know that?
I know.
Well, then maybe he's
in the wrong line of work.
Hmm.
You engineering types
don't appreciate imagination?
That's not it, Guinan.
He just doesn't fit in here.
Oh.
Terkim.
What?
Reminds me of Terkim.
My mother's brother.
Sort of the family misfit.
Everybody told me
to stay away from him.
Bad influence.
Did you?
Are you kidding?
He was the only member
of my family
who had a sense of humor.
Except no one ever stayed
around him long enough
to realize it but me.
My mother tells me I remind her
of him, and I probably do.
The idea of fitting in
just... repels me.
Maybe I'm not
making myself clear, Guinan.
Barclay--
well, he's always late.
The man's nervous.
Nobody wants
to be around this guy.
If I felt that nobody
wanted to be around me
I'd probably be late
and nervous, too.
Guinan, that's not the point.
Are you sure?
Excuse me.
Computer,
where is Lieutenant Barclay?
( birds singing )
( holodeck doors close )
Reg?
Beverly?
Good morning, milord.
Manners, my son, manners.
You embarrass me
before our guest.
Master Barclay
will spank you
if you misbehave.
Wesley?
What do you want?
Well, I guess
I want Master Barclay.
The boys got into another
little scrap, I'm afraid
but boys will be boys.
( swords clashing,
men grunting )
You cannot withstand our
assault forever, Barclay.
Ah!
Ha!
DATA:
You are outnumbered,
Mr. Barclay.
Say you will yield,
and it ends here.
I shall speak
with my sword, sir.
Ha!
In God's name
where did you learn
to fight like this?
Self-taught,
my Capitaine.
Shall I give you
a few lessons?
PICARD:
Who is that?
One of your allies?
Oh, Jean-Luc
not that old trick.
I'm very disappointed in you.
( clears throat )
I'll make it easy
for you, Commander.
I will request
a reassignment.
Now, wait...
Look, we both know--
The whole ship knows...
I... I just can't
cut it here.
Hey, Barclay
I've spent a few hours
on the holodeck, too, you know.
Now, as far
as I'm concerned
what you do in the holodeck
is your own business
as long as it doesn't
interfere with your work.
So you're...
you're not going to
tell anyone about this?
I don't think everybody
would appreciate
your imagination like I do.
It is kind of unusual
recreating people
you already know.
Well, it was just...
I needed to blow
off some steam
because one...
one of the officers
had been getting
on my back.
Let me guess.
( laughs )
It was you.
And I just couldn't tell you
what I wanted to tell you
to your face
so it just sort
of got out of control.
I don't know, there's a part of
this
that's kind of therapeutic.
Maybe you ought to talk
to Counselor Troi about it.
It's, it's... I'm ...
when I'm in there,
I'm just more comfortable.
You don't know what a struggle
this has been for me, Commander.
Well, I'd like to help if I can.
Being afraid
all of the time
of forgetting somebody's name
not... not knowing what to do
with your hands.
I mean, I am the guy
who writes down
things to remember to say
when there's a party.
And then when he
finally gets there
he winds up alone,
in the corner
trying to look
comfortable
examining a potted plant.
You're just shy, Barclay.
"Just shy."
sounds like nothing serious,
doesn't it?
You can't know.
O'Brien to La Forge.
Go ahead.
I need you in transporter
room three, Commander.
On my way, Chief.
Listen, Reg.
I really do want you
to talk to Counselor Troi.
Troi?
No, no, no, no, no.
I... I couldn't.
I mean it.
As your friend
and as your commanding officer.
I was synchronizing
the phase transition coils.
I didn't do anything
I haven't done 100 times before.
The test object
is made of pure duranium.
Seems normal
enough to me.
Watch this.
Glad I don't have
anywhere to go.
LA FORGE:
Chief Engineer's log,
Stardate 43808.2.
A systems analysis
of transporter room three
has yielded no suggestion
of a cause
for the latest malfunction
aboard the Enterprise.
This part of the same pattern?
We don't know, sir.
And we don't know why
only transporter room
three is affected.
None of the other transporter
rooms are malfunctioning.
Yet.
We reach Nahmi IV in 22 hours.
We'll want all transporters
operational by then.
I want a level-1 diagnostic
across the board.
Advise Mr. Barclay to join us
on the bridge immediately.
Oh, can we make
that 1400 hours, sir?
I've got him working
on something.
1400 hours.
Mr. O'brien, no maintenance
on the transporter
until further notice.
Aye, sir.
I know this is
difficult for you.
Is there anything I can do
to make you more comfortable?
No.
Have you ever been
with a counselor before?
Yes... no.
Which one?
Yes, but she, uh...
It-it wasn't...
it wasn't really a counselor.
Most people find a counselor
intimidating at first.
It's okay if you feel
that way toward me.
Not... at all.
Good.
Now, lean back,
close your eyes...
Why?
I want to make you
more comfortable.
You do?
Yes.
It's okay.
Close your eyes.
What are you
going to do?
Just listen to the sound
of my voice.
Take a slow, deep breath
in through your nose...
... and let it out through
your mouth just as slowly.
That's better, isn't it?
Much better.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes, that's...
that's much better.
That... that...
that is extremely helpful.
Thank you
for your time.
But...
Really, that's
very helpful.
In through the nose
out through the mouth.
I'm going to practice that
and I'll-I'll let you know.
Thank you again.
Whoa...oh
I had a very
strange visit
from one of your
officers today.
Barclay?
Yeah, I can imagine.
Were you able to do
anything for him?
To be honest I'm not
sure what happened.
Where is Mr. Barclay?
It's past 1400 hours.
Lieutenant Barclay,
report to the bridge.
Lieutenant Barclay, report.
Computer,
locate Lieutenant Barclay.
COMPUTER: Lieutenant Barclay
is in holodeck two.
( sighs ):
I'll get him.
No, I'll
handle this.
I've had it with him.
Counselor, you'd
better come along.
I think
you should know
Barclay's been running
some unique programs.
I don't care
what he's been running.
I just ran out of patience.
( birds singing )
( men laughing in the distance )
( holodeck door closes )
PICARD:
...before our swords.
MEN:
Hear, hear.
( laughter )
PICARD:
I hope she was worth
the effort.
GEORDIE:
Oh. Show us how you did it.
DATA:
Like this!
Ah!
Like I said, Commander
Barclay's been running
some unusual programs.
This is a violation
of protocol.
Crewmembers should not be
simulated in the holodeck.
LA FORGE:
Commander, I don't
think there's any
regulation against...
Well, there ought to be.
Computer, discontinue
program and erase.
Computer, belay that order.
Counselor?
If Barclay is having
difficulty facing reality
to suddenly destroy
his only means of escape
would be brutal
and could do
considerable damage.
They are quite disagreeable,
aren't they?
Mmm.
Shall we...
have at them?
Delighted!
GEORDIE:
We shall thrash them.
En garde!
Stop it.
Put that down.
Your sword, sir.
I don't have a sword.
How do you expect to fight
without your sword, sir?
I don't expect to fight.
Ha!
Do I detect
a streak of yellow
along the good
fellow's back?
( laughing )
Perhaps we should supply
a more appropriate
adversary for him.
GEORDIE:
Aha, indeed.
Number one?
Number one!
RIKER:
Here I come.
Am I late?
Did I miss the fight?
En garde!
You, sir, you have
a familiar bearing.
Is it possible our swords
have crossed somewhere before?
Where is he?
Where's Barclay?
Aha! A personal grudge.
I warn you, it would
be wise for you
to put your affairs
in final order
before you meet him
in combat.
You challenge
the greatest sword...
In all the holodeck.
( stifles laughter )
You think this is funny?
You are very tall.
It might be threatening
to some people.
Mr. Barclay will find out
what it means to be threatened.
Computer,
discontinue image of Riker.
Sir!
You have no sense of fair play.
Just tell us
where to find Barclay.
You want us to
search through all
this to find him?
It could provide us
with valuable information
about what's troubling him.
You know, there's nothing wrong
with a healthy fantasy life
as long as you
don't let it take over.
You call this healthy?
You're taking it
so seriously.
It's not without
its element of humor.
I am the goddess
of empathy.
Cast off your inhibitions
and embrace love
truth, joy.
Oh... my... God.
Discard your facades
and reveal
your true being to me.
Computer, discontinue...
Computer, belay
that order.
We want to get
more insight
into what's
been troubling this
poor man, remember?
Quite a healthy
fantasy life
wouldn't you say?
Mmm.
( rumbling )
( console beeping )
Report.
WORF:
Sir, our velocity
increased to warp 7.25.
Compensating, sir.
Confirmed.
Velocity now warp seven.
Maintain that.
What the hell happened?
The matter/anti-matter
injectors locked
for a split second.
I am not certain why, sir.
They appear to be
working normally now.
Picard to La Forge.
LA FORGE: Go ahead,
Captain.
Commander, any explanation
for this injector problem?
Well, um, I'm not
in engineering, sir.
I'm in holodeck two.
PICARD:
Another malfunction?
Not exactly, but I'll
return to engineering
immediately, sir.
Yes, I should say
that you should, Commander.
Your holodeck activities
can wait until later.
And, Commander...
Yes, sir.
It would be wise to consult
Lieutenant Barclay
on this latest incident.
I'd like to
very much, Captain.
La Forge out.
We need to find
Barclay now.
Cast aside your masks
and let me slip into your minds.
Muzzle it.
( loud snoring )
Shh.
We have a lot to talk
about, Mr. Barclay.
Commander,
Barclay and I
had better get
to engineering.
Dismissed.
I just couldn't
keep my eyes open.
I'd worked 12 hours
on the power systems
and then... then the
transporter went down.
Reg, you had a chance
to get some help
from the real
Counselor Troi
but, instead, you
went back in there.
I know.
I didn't want to.
I just couldn't
help myself.
You're going to be
able to write the
book on holodiction.
Look, I know
how easy it is
to get caught
up in it.
I fell in love
in there once.
Really?
But I knew when
it was time
to turn it off
and say good-bye.
It wasn't easy,
but I did it.
You know, the people
that I create in there
are more real to me
than anyone I meet out here.
Except...
maybe you,
Commander.
I need you
out here, Reg.
Now more than ever.
Huh?
The injectors aren't responding
to the diagnostic commands.
I think we should
drop out of warp.
La Forge to bridge.
Go ahead, Commander.
Recommend we go
to impulse power, Captain.
Take us out of warp.
Controls are not
responding, sir.
It's the injectors.
Override.
It's not
a computer problem.
The mechanism is
physically jammed.
I can't clear it.
Speed increasing, sir.
Warp 7.6.
7.65.
Warp 7.7.
We can't shut it
down, Captain.
Anti-matter flow
is... increasing.
She's accelerating
out of control.
There's nothing I can do.
Approaching
warp nine, sir.
Red alert.
Estimated time
to structural failure?
At this rate of acceleration--
15 minutes, 40 seconds, sir.
Did you copy that, Geordi?
Aye, Commander.
Recommendations?
I'll let you know
as soon as we have some.
La Forge out.
Okay, this ship
is going to start
tearing itself apart
in 15 minutes.
I want every idea on the table,
I don't care how outrageous.
What about attempting
a magnetic quench
on the fusion
pre-burners?
No, I already tried that.
The magnetic fields won't reset.
Could the fuel inlet servos
be caught in cycle?
If they were,
the swirl dampers
would be frozen, too,
and they aren't.
Nothing showed up
in the diagnostic sweep, at all?
The tests showed
there were proble...
I mean, there were
no problems
with the fl-flow...
the flow of the...
There's nothing wrong
with the computer
control protocols
or the power
transfer systems.
As far as we can
determine the injectors
are just
physically jammed.
Injectors freeze,
antigrav unit goes down
transporter malfunctions...
And a twisted glass.
What's the connection?
( rumbling )
Exceeding warp 9.4.
Begin evacuation
of secondary hull.
Prepare for emergency
saucer separation.
Standing by to release
docking clamps.
Re-route systems
to primary hull power sources.
The plasma flow to the nacelles
is uneven due to injector lock.
An emergency saucer separation
could rupture the warp field.
( rumbling )
( console beeping insistently )
12 minutes
to structural failure, sir.
None of the
systems involved
interact directly
with each other.
I don't see
anything in common.
Wh-what if... what if...
what if one of us
is the connection?
Us? How?
I don't know.
But we're looking
for a systemic explanation
and there isn't one.
I mean, we work with
all of the systems
that are affected.
What if...
what if we're transmitting
something ourselves...
by touching it, or something?
The computer would have
picked up anything dangerous.
But... if it were something,
something that
we couldn't scan
you might have passed it on
to the injectors
when you were re-aligning
the magnetic capacitors.
It was your glass, Duffy,
and both of you were present
in the cargo bay
when the antigrav failed.
Well, so was O'Brien.
The transporter malfunction--
that's a connection, too.
( alarm beeps loudly )
COMPUTER: Danger!
Approaching safety limits
of engine containment field.
Computer,
list all physical substances
that wouldn't normally be
picked up by an internal scan.
There are 15,525
known substances
that cannot be detected
by standard scans.
Great, and how many of those can
exist in an oxygen atmosphere?
Five hundred thirty-two.
And could alter
molecular structure
when it comes in contact with...
with glass?
Five.
On screen at this station.
Duffy.
BARCLAY:
Jakmanite has a half-life
of 15 seconds.
There wouldn't be enough time
to spread it around the ship.
Right.
Selgninaem and lucrovexitrin
are highly toxic.
Yeah, we'd all be dead by now.
That leaves...
saltzgadum and invidium.
Neither of which has been used
for decades.
But could either one of them
cause all these malfunctions?
Most of the affected systems
weren't even invented
when those substances
were in use.
Who knows what could happen
with a transporter
or a magnetic capacitor.
Wait a minute,
wasn't invidium used
in medical containment fields?
Not for over a century.
The Mikulaks
might still be using it.
And one of those canisters
was broken.
La Forge to bridge.
We have a working theory,
Captain.
There's a good possibility
we picked up some invidium
from a broken canister
in the cargo bay
and have been spreading it
around the ship.
Working theories
are fine, Geordi
but we need a working solution
in about five minutes.
Understood, Commander.
We're on our way to cargo bay
five for confirmation.
Nothing on the tricorder.
( alarm beeps loudly )
COMPUTER: Danger.
Exceeding safety limits
of engine containment field.
At current acceleration
structural failure will occur
in three minutes, 30 seconds.
If it's in there,
it should show up
on one of the
polarity channels.
There it is.
Duffy and O'Brien picked up
the broken canister
and became contaminated.
If we can get it--
the invidium--
down to minus 200 degrees
celsius, it'll become inert.
La Forge to bridge.
Invidium has been confirmed.
Recommend we flood
the injector pathway conduit
with gaseous cryonetrium.
That ought to neutralize it.
The question is, will the
injectors come back on-line?
They sustained
considerable damage, Captain.
I can't guarantee that we'll
be able to regain control.
We don't have
much choice, do we?
No, sir.
Make it so.
DUFFY:
Route primary coupling through
starboard transfer conduit.
Routing.
Ready for engine
core injection.
COMPUTER:
At current acceleration
structural failure
will occur in 45 seconds.
Injector conduit temperature
minus 100 degrees celsius.
Transfer injector
control to manual.
Ready, sir.
Temperature now
minus 190 degrees.
Minus 200 degrees, sir.
Injector status?
Matter injector is on-line.
Anti-matter injector...
still locked.
( alarm beeps loudly )
COMPUTER:
At current acceleration
structural failure
will occur in 30 seconds.
Cycle power
through ventral relay.
Anti-matter injector...
on-line.
Reducing flow capacity.
Commencing
warp engine shutdown, sir.
Stand down
from red alert.
Nice work, Geordi.
Mr. Barclay and I
thank you, sir.
RIKER:
Acknowledged.
The ship has been
seriously contaminated
with invidium, sir.
Recommend we set a course
for Starbase 121
for a complete systems-
and bio-decontamination.
Understood.
Picard out.
Glad you were with us
out here in the real
world today, Mr. Barclay.
It has been most difficult
to reach this decision
to leave you
but after thinking about it
and discussing it
at length with...
Counselor Troi
I think it's
for the best.
I just wanted to thank you all
for your support.
You'll always be
welcome here, Reg.
I know.
That's why
it's so difficult to leave.
It was a pleasure to serve
with you, Mr. Barclay.
Good luck, Reg.
It's been fun.
Computer.
End program.
( computer beeps )
Erase all programs
filed under Reginald Barclay.
( computer beeps )
Except program nine.
♪♪