Captain's Log,
Stardate 43872.2.
In order to neutralize
a sudden contamination
of the water supply
at the Federation colony
on Beta Agni Two,
we are procuring 108 kilos
of hytritium
from the Zibalian trader,
Kivas Fajo.
Because pure hytritium
is too unstable
for our transporters,
Lieutenant Commander Data
has been shuttling the material
to the Enterprise.
Data to Enterprise.
PICARD:
Go ahead, Mr. Data.
This will be the last trip,
sir.
The remaining cases of hytritium
are now being loaded.
Acknowledged.
Mr. Worf,
advise Beta Agni Two
that our departure is imminent.
WORF:
Aye, Captain.
At warp six, we should be there
at just over 16 hours.
Loading is complete.
I am now proceeding
with departure.
Enterprise shuttle bay two,
prepare for docking.
Level one precautions
for incoming material
remain in effect.
If you'll just acknowledge
this last load, Commander.
26.8 kilos tripolymer
composites.
11.8 kilos
molybdenum-cobalt alloy.
1.3 kilos bioplast sheeting.
LA FORGE:
Shuttle 12 containment field
reads nominal.
Now leaving the Jovis.
On viewer.
Containment field stable.
Gravitational fluctuations
within acceptable parameters.
Flight pattern...
Data.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
As the result of a yet
unexplained shuttle explosion,
Lieutenant Commander Data
has been lost.
RIKER: Why didn't the
containment field hold?
LA FORGE:
Unknown, Commander.
Hail the Jovis. I want to speak
with Kivas Fajo.
Sir, Mr. Fajo
is hailing us.
On viewer.
Captain Picard,
what happened?
It's unclear.
We're running
a full analysis.
We detected no malfunctions
before the explosion.
Everything seemed to be running
as smoothly
as the other flights.
Were you able to save the pilot?
No.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Fajo,
I would like to analyze
your sensor readings
of the explosion.
Compared to the Enterprise's,
our sensors are
rather primitive.
I doubt they contain any
information that your sensors
overlooked.
Perhaps, but I don't want to
leave any avenue unexplored.
I understand.
We'll transmit the information.
Link established.
Receiving.
Can we be of any further
assistance?
How much hytritium
did we manage
to bring on board?
81 kilos.
That may barely allow us to
complete our mission, Captain,
but it leaves us no margin
for error.
Mr. Fajo, I realize we have
acquired
your entire supply
of hytritium.
Do you know where
we could obtain some more?
That may be difficult.
The only source I know is in
the Sigma Erani system?
Three weeks away, sir.
And I can't guarantee
they'll have any.
For obvious reasons, no one
wants to keep it around.
In fact, even I may stop
selling it.
It's just too dangerous.
I guess we're fortunate
you had any at all, sir.
Captain, transfer of
information complete.
Mr. Fajo...
thank you for your help.
Mr. Crusher, set a course for
the Beta Agni Two system.
Warp six.
Aye, sir.
The Grissom's near the
Sigma Erani system.
I'll alert them to stand by in
case we need more hytritium.
Thank you, Number One.
Course laid in, sir.
Engage.
What am I doing here?
( door opens )
Oh. Wondrous.
The detail, the balance.
Was I not right, Varria?
Oh, what a remarkable
piece of work, hmm?
Why have I
been brought here?
Oh!
The... the voice simulation.
It's... it's perfection.
The inflections,
the timing.
( snapping fingers )
( laughing )
( clears throat )
Yes, uh, it took great
effort, effort...
to bring you here.
I was sure
it would be worth it.
I was right.
I've been delivered here
against my wishes.
I would like
to know the reason.
Certainly.
You have been brought here
for my... enjoyment
and my appreciation.
Am I to infer that you intend
to keep me captive?
Captive? Captive?
Oh, it's such
an inappropriate description.
My dear android...
may I call you Data?
It is my name.
Data, you will be catered to,
fawned over,
cared for as you never
have been before.
Your every wish
will be fulfilled.
I wish to leave.
Almost every wish.
This is unacceptable, sir.
I have no desire to remain here,
and even if I did,
my Starfleet duties
would not allow it.
It's so...
single-minded, isn't it?
Very persistent.
But it's polite,
which is a very nice touch.
I decline to allow you to go.
Then I am forced
to attempt escape.
Uh, ten androids
just like you might be able
to force that thing open.
But then again, there aren't any
more just like you, are there?
It's keyed to galvanic
skin responses
and DNA patterns.
Sorry.
Then you will have to open it
for me.
Oh.
Really, I wouldn't do that
again if I were you.
This is a proximity-actuated
field.
It impedes positron flow.
It's very bad for the brain
paths in the long term.
I fail to understand
the value you place
on my presence.
Well, just look
around the room.
There are items here gathered
from half the galaxy.
Right here--
this is the very first basotile
ever created.
Oh, sorry.
It's very, very ancient.
Hundreds of years old.
Oh, it's priceless.
Come. This vase?
This vase is made
by Mark Off...
the late Mark Off-Zel
from Sirrie-Four.
A Dali.
This...
this is the only known
Roger Maris trading card
from Earth, circa 1962.
The smell?
Bubble gum--
I've preserved the scent.
Ah.
Uh... what, what?
Ah, a lapling.
( humming )
I thought they were extinct.
Extinct? Oh, good.
Yes, well, that is what
is generally believed.
She is the last surviving
member of her species.
( humming )
( chuckles )
They're very defenseless
creatures, really.
Everything that you see
in the room here, everything,
one of a kind, unique.
All original.
Just as you are.
There, that is your
place of honor.
( chuckles )
Sit, sit.
Sit.
You think perhaps it might
be uncomfortable?
But then again, you don't give a
thought to comfort, do you?
When Palor Toff learns of that,
he'll swallow his tongue
with envy.
I can't wait to see his face.
You... you are, um...
the crown jewel
of my collection.
You're a treasure
beyond comparison.
( beeping )
Yes, go ahead.
I think you should be flattered.
I am not, sir.
Most intelligent life-forms
find involuntary confinement
offensive and inequitable.
Moreover, you have violated
Federation law--
I know, I know.
What I've done is evil, selfish,
immoral, unprincipled, illegal.
Well I've learned to
live with it.
The Andorians
wish to make a bid
on the shipment
of Tellurian spices you offered.
They've had four days to decide!
Why do they decide right--
All right.
I must emphasize,
Mr. Fajo,
that I consider this captivity
a hostile act on your part.
Oh. Well, you'll
get used to it.
( screeches )
I can't believe he's gone.
Yeah, well I always thought
he'd outlive us by centuries.
He'd been working on this
for months.
Never felt it was
quite finished.
You know what a critic
Data was,
especially about
his own work.
That was a gift from the
captain.
And he should have it back.
Those should go
to Commander Riker.
Data always fell
for Riker's bluffs.
( whistles )
These are some of Starfleet's
highest honors.
Not bad for a walking
pile of circuitry
and memory cells.
You know,
I keep going over and over
the accident in my mind
trying to figure out
what went wrong.
I can see Data
in the shuttle
almost like
I'm sitting there next to him
going through
the departure sequence.
What the hell happened?
Why didn't I see it coming?
What am I missing?
Kivas wishes you to wear
this set of clothes
and to sit
in your chair.
I have no reason to accede
to Mr. Fajo's wishes.
He will give
you reasons
if you force him to.
Mr. Fajo is deluding himself if
he believes he can keep me here.
The Enterprise is certain
to find me.
They're not even
looking for you.
They think you're destroyed.
Your shuttle blew up.
A hytritium explosion.
They will scan the debris and
discover I was not aboard.
They'll find exactly what they
thought they'd find--
traces of your
component elements.
We put them aboard the shuttle
in just the right proportions.
Clearly, Mr. Fajo
has no moral difficulty
with my imprisonment here.
Mr. Fajo has
no moral difficulties at all.
Do you?
Clever, android.
Is it part of your program
to seek out vulnerabilities
in your enemies?
Yes. Are you my enemy?
I obey Fajo and so does everyone
on this ship.
Why?
You are a curious thing,
aren't you?
Do you object to the question?
Kivas finds ways to get
what he wants from his people.
His rewards for loyalty
are lavish.
His punishments for
disloyalty are equally...
lavish.
You won't find anyone
here on this ship
to help you escape.
Face it, android.
He has you.
It appears...
he has us both.
The reason
I can't find anything
is that there's
nothing to find.
I've run this analysis
dozen's of times over,
and there's just no indication
of any malfunction.
No explanation at all?
Oh, yeah, there's one,
but I don't believe it.
Pilot error?
I know it's hard to accept,
but even the best...
Captain, it's not only hard
to accept with Data,
it's impossible.
I mean, I can't even begin
to calculate the odds.
It's...
well, if Data were here,
we could ask him.
What are you suggesting,
Lieutenant?
I don't know, sir.
It just doesn't
make sense.
And I like for things
to make sense, that's all.
Geordi, maybe if you got
a little rest,
and you came at this
thing fresh.
A little rest isn't going to
change the computer analysis,
Commander.
I'm sure you have done
a complete investigation,
and if you wish to continue it,
of course, you have my full
support.
But we shall be reaching
the Beta Agni system shortly,
and I expect you to be rested.
I understand, sir.
Dismissed.
Geordi...
I understand
how much we want...
( sighs )
even need to explain
an accident like this.
Sometimes there just aren't
any explanations.
For an android
with no feelings,
he sure managed
to evoke them in others.
We must select an officer
to replace Data at ops.
Recommendations?
Worf would be
my first choice, sir.
Mine as well.
Make it so.
"He was a man.
"Take him for all in all.
I shall not look upon
his like again."
Lu-lu-lu-lu-lu.
Lu-lu.
You are still wearing
that uniform. Why?
I am a Starfleet officer.
You are not
in Starfleet any longer.
It's time you adjusted
your program to accept reality.
Even if I chose to do so, it is
doubtful that my program
could be sufficiently altered
to accede to your wishes.
Oh?
I have been designed
with a fundamental respect for
life in all its forms
and a strong inhibition against
causing harm to living beings.
What a marvelous
contradiction--
a military pacifist.
Tell me, whose
dreadful idea was it
to enlist you in Starfleet
to begin with?
My skills seemed appropriate
to...
Data, Data, Data,
big mistake, grievous error.
You belong in Starfleet
about as much as I belong
in a verbal contract.
Tell me, Data,
have you killed yet?
No, but I am programmed
with the ability to use deadly
force in the cause of defense.
Shame on you.
How neatly you rationalize
your capabilities.
How can you just casually
accept your role in murder?
I would not participate
in a murder.
Perhaps you misunderstand.
Can't you see how much better
it would be for you right here?
The intellectual rewards
alone...
our personal exploration
of the galaxy.
I am at war with no one.
I'm your liberator.
You are a fine debater, sir.
It is a pity you have used
your verbal skills
for mere hucksterism
and the advancement
of your own greed.
Perhaps...
perhaps you would not judge me
so harshly
if you knew
of my desperate youth wasted...
wasted on the streets
of Zibalia.
Your past does not excuse
unethical or immoral
behavior, sir.
No it doesn't matter,
it isn't true anyway.
My father was quite wealthy,
actually.
He was a thief.
Data, why don't you put on
these lovely new clothes
and go sit on the chair.
I must decline.
You're going to be
much more of a challenge
than I had first thought.
Finoplak. 100 denkirs.
Now, Data, in the meantime,
here is something
for your logic circuits
to analyze.
Don't worry, the solvent
won't harm your... skin.
But in seconds,
it will completely
dissolve
that uniform.
Personally, I'd be
delighted to see you
go around naked.
I assume you have no modesty.
But then, I guess
that decency is the rule
of your
Starfleet training.
In any case, Data
why don't you
make a decision
about which alternative
you dislike the least.
Make a decision
by dinnertime tonight.
I've invited
a guest to meet you.
And I expect you to be
as entertaining with him
as you have been with me.
DATA:
Proceeding with departure.
Enterprise, shuttle bay two,
prepare for docking.
Level one precautions
remain in effect.
I did miss something.
Your first watch at ops?
I have served at
the position before.
I've been concerned
about you.
About me? Why?
Because I know
how I'd feel
if I was asked to replace
Data at his station.
Bridge.
Promotion due to the death
of a crew mate
is commonplace
on Klingon ships.
I know, but this
isn't the Klingon ship
and Data was your friend,
and it's the second time
you've replaced
a crew mate who's died.
I honor Data's memory
as I did Lieutenant Yar's
by attempting
to perform their duties
as well as they did.
In true Klingon fashion.
I appreciate your concern.
Computer, now replay
shuttle audio transmission
time index: 0423.
This is Data's second trip.
Hmm? All right.
DATA:
Proceeding with departure.
Enterprise shuttle bay two,
prepare for docking.
Level one precautions
remain in effect.
Shuttle has cleared
Jovis cargo bay.
It sounds just like
the first trip.
Exactly the same.
That's protocol
and that's Data--
following protocol
to the letter.
Okay, computer, now replay
shuttle audio transmission
time index: 0439.
Third and final trip.
DATA:
Loading is complete.
I am proceeding with departure.
Enterprise shuttle bay two,
prepare for docking.
Level one precautions
remain in effect.
That's it. That's the last
communication.
He didn't report the shuttle
clearing the cargo bay
of the Jovis.
Of course, there really wasn't
any reason for him to make voice
contact.
He knew we'd be monitoring
his position.
Any other pilot might not even
have bothered.
But Data, not following
standard procedures?
What do you think it means?
I'm not sure, Wes.
I suppose he could have
been too busy.
Maybe he saw something
was wrong.
Without communicating it?
That doesn't sound like Data,
either.
Which means that maybe
something was wrong with him
but there's no other
indication of that--
nothing he said or did during
the entire mission-- none.
Sure wish I could talk
to the last people
who saw him alive.
( door chimes )
I've added a Veltan sex idol
to my collection.
I got four of them.
What?
With the pearls intact?
Please!
Pearls were added
by Ferengi agents
to increase
the value.
What is that?
Something new
and you didn't tell me.
Mr. Data, I'm
delighted to see
that you dressed
for the occasion.
Say hello to my very
good friend, Palor Toff.
Uh...
Data?
Say hello.
No need to be shy.
It's a mannequin of some sort.
This is not a mannequin,
this is Data.
This is formerly
Lieutenant Commander Data
of the Federation Starfleet.
The only sentient android
in existence.
It doesn't seem
particularly sentient right now.
That's cause it's playing a
stupid little game with us.
Well, someone has certainly
played a game on you, Fajo.
I don't find this amusing.
I demand
that you behave normally.
Behave... normally!
I know you can hear me!
He falls well.
I apologize for this.
Do not be upset,
my friend.
I'm having a delightful visit.
Come along,
Varria.
You're much
more fun
than Fajo's new toy.
You'll regret this.
Now entering
the Beta Agni system, sir.
Half-impulse,
Mr. Crusher.
La Forge to bridge.
Go ahead, Commander.
Captain, a class-two probe
has been loaded
with the hytritium compound
and is ready to launch.
Now approaching Beta Agni Two,
sir.
Mr. Crusher, put us into close
orbit.
Mr. Data, scan...
My apologies, Mr. Worf.
Scan the colony's
subsurface water.
Scanning.
Tricyanate contamination
confirmed.
Levels approaching
42 parts per million.
Area affected?
30 square
kilometers.
Any indication of source?
Highest concentration eight
kilometers west of the colony.
Adjust target coordinates.
Aye, sir.
La Forge to bridge.
According to these figures,
the 81 kilos
of hytritium should be enough
to neutralize the contamination.
Now approaching target
coordinates.
Launch probe.
Probe on target.
Hytritium entering water table.
Disbursement slightly
faster than expected.
Sir,
something unusual.
Specify.
I'm getting concentrated
tricyanate readings
of 70 grams per cubic centimeter
at the source coordinates--
much higher than
would normally occur.
Computer, report on geological
instability on Beta Agni Two.
COMPUTER:
No significant
geological activity
has been recorded
on Beta Agni Two
since the settlement of the
Federation colony.
Number One, perhaps you better
take an away team down and have
a closer look.
Aye, sir.
Dr. Crusher, join me
in transporter room three.
BEVERLY:
On my way.
Mr. Worf.
I would very much like our
relationship to...change.
You may expect me to use every
means at my disposal
to resist your wishes.
Why couldn't you just comply?
Why do you have to argue
all the time?
Couldn't you just go sit
on the chair?
Come on, go sit on the chair.
I do not intend to sit
in the chair.
You will.
You may not believe it
right now,
but you will.
Oh...
Have you ever seen
one of these, Data?
It is a disrupter.
Well...no, it's a prototype
for a Varon-T disrupter.
The Varon-T disrupter is banned
in the Federation.
Oh, yes, they only manufactured
five of them. I own four.
I sleep with one under my pillow
at night, and I sleep very well
knowing it's there, too.
Do you know why?
It is a most lethal weapon.
It's not just lethal, it's...
it's vicious.
It tears a body apart,
inside-out,
and does it very slowly, too,
by your phaser standards.
It's a tortuous, very...
very painful death.
I've always wanted to try this.
It is doubtful
you will destroy me
since you assign so much value
to possessing me.
That goes without saying.
Please come in.
Varria, how long have we
been together, my dear?
14 years.
14 wonderful years
they were, too.
She was barely an adult
when I found her.
She was idealistic,
naive and full of dreams
and I made those dreams come
true, too, didn't I?
I'm going to miss you.
DATA:
Fajo.
The contamination
has been neutralized.
The water is clean.
WORF:
Curious.
The process of neutralization
should have taken several hours.
Naturally-occurring tricyanate
does not respond this quickly.
Are you saying
it's not naturally occurring?
There are no natural
trace elements present
in these tricyanate crystals.
If it's artificial then we're
talking about sabotage.
BEVERLY:
With tricyanate?
That's hard to believe.
It's slow to assimilate,
difficult to replicate
and hard to transport.
There are a lot easier ways
to poison a water supply.
More effective ways, too.
Can you think of any reason a
saboteur
would choose tricyanate?
It might pass
for a natural disaster.
And since there's only one way
to treat it, with hytritium,
maybe somebody figured
we couldn't locate it.
It is hard to find.
Then it really was
lucky, wasn't it?
That we were able to find
hytritium when we did.
And just enough hytritium
for this crisis.
Fajo was in the right place
at the right time,
just when we needed him most.
Are you suggesting he created
the problem just to solve it?
Possibly.
LA FORGE:
What, to make a profit
from his sale of hytritium?
It doesn't add up.
The cost of producing tricyanate
is very expensive.
He wouldn't make a profit on it.
Quite the contrary.
Then why would he do it?
What did he want?
Computer, biographical file
on trader Kivas Fajo.
COMPUTER:
Accessing file.
Kivas Fajo, a Zibalian trader
of the Stacius trade guild
educated on Iraatin Five.
A noted collector
of rare and valuable objects
including the Rejac crystal,
the Starry Night by Vincent
Van Gogh,
the Lawmin galactopedia,
the Malia Manda tapestry...
Computer, that is sufficient.
A rare and valuable object.
What if Data
wasn't on that shuttle?
Mr. Crusher.
CRUSHER:
Aye, sir.
Set course for the site
of the shuttlepod explosion.
Warp eight.
Aye, sir.
The Jovis has a maximum speed
of warp three.
He's had 23 hours.
So we can define a perimeter
of .102 light-years
as his possible distance
distance.
Fajo doesn't know that
we're onto him.
So he probably isn't taxing
his engines top speed.
He could have made it
to the Nel Bato system
or maybe even the Giles belt.
He's a trader.
He doesn't attract customers
by being hard to find.
We could put out a coded Level
Two query to all Federation
outposts
within the perimeter.
Make it so.
If I help you escape,
will you take me with you?
He's sleeping.
And there isn't
much time.
The consequences
if we are caught...
I know
the consequences.
14 years...
you learn a few things.
There's an escape pod
in the aft cargo bay.
Captain, affirmative response
from station Lya-Four.
Fajo spent more than
half a day in orbit.
Departed just over
seven hours ago.
Mr. Crusher, new coordinates.
Lay in a course for Lya-Four.
Course already
laid in, sir.
Perhaps I should attempt
to communicate
with the Enterprise.
You can't.
Fajo has communications access
restricted to the bridge.
Once we're out,
the shuttle pod will emit
an emergency beacon.
We'll just have to hope
somebody responds
before Fajo is able
to destroy us.
I am trained
in evasive maneuvers.
We'll need a few.
Let's get going.
As soon as I start
the escape sequence
an alarm will sound.
We won't have much time.
( alarm siren )
VARRIA:
Oh, no!
( screaming )
It's your fault.
You knew the price
for disobedience.
And so did she.
Well, there's always
another Varria.
You won't hurt me.
"Fundamental respect
for all living beings."
That's what you said.
I'm a living being.
Therefore, you can't harm me.
You will surrender yourself
to the authorities.
Or what?
You'll fire?
Empty threat
and we both know it.
Why don't you
accept your fate?
You'll return
to your chair
and you will
sit there.
You will entertain me and you
will entertain my guests.
And if you don't,
I'll simply kill
someone else.
Him, perhaps.
Doesn't matter.
Their blood will be
on your hands, too,
just like poor Varria's.
Your only
alternative, Data,
is to fire.
Murder me.
That's all you have to do.
Go ahead, fire.
If only you could feel rage
over Varria's death.
If only you could feel
a need for revenge,
then maybe you could fire.
But you're just an android.
You can't feel
anything, can you?
It's just another interesting
intellectual puzzle for you,
another of life's curiosities.
I cannot permit this
to continue.
Wait, your program
won't allow you to fire.
You can't fire.
No.
I'm reading a weapon
in transit with commander Data.
It seems to have
discharged, sir.
Discharged?
I'm deactivating it.
Welcome back, Mr. Data.
Are you all right?
Yes, Commander.
Please arrange to have
Kivas Fajo taken into custody
on charges of murder,
kidnapping, theft...
The arrangements have
already been made.
A Varon-T disrupter.
It belongs to Fajo.
Mr. O'Brien says the weapon was
in a state of discharge.
Perhaps something occurred
during transport, Commander.
Oh, have you come
to see me repent?
Your final satisfaction?
Want to see me
beg for mercy?
You're not going to get
any of that from me.
I expected nothing.
Our roles are reversed.
Aren't they, Data?
You're the collector now.
Me, I'm in a cage.
So it seems.
Don't count me out
too quickly.
I had you in my collection once.
I can have you there again.
Unlikely, sir.
Your collection
has been confiscated.
All of your stolen possessions
are being returned
to their rightful owners.
You have lost everything
you value.
That must give you
great pleasure.
No, sir, it does not.
I do not feel pleasure.
I am only an android.