Captain's Log,
Stardate 43917.4.
The Enterprise has been given
the singular honor of hosting
the first meeting
between the Federation
and a mysterious race
known as the Legarans.
We are in orbit around Vulcan
preparing to welcome aboard
Federation Ambassador Sarek
and his wife, Perrin
who, like his first wife,
is from Earth.
I remember studying
his career in school.
The treaty of
Alpha Cygnus IX,
the Coridan admission
to the Federation,
the Klingon alliance...
I met him once,
many years ago
very briefly,
at his son's wedding.
I can tell you
that was quite a moment
for a young lieutenant.
Standing in the presence
of such history.
I remember he spoke to me
and I just stood there,
grinning like an idiot.
Captain...
You tongue-tied?
Indeed. How do you make
small talk
with someone
who shaped the Federation?
Is it true he'll
be retiring after
this mission?
Unofficially,
that's what I hear.
What a crowning
achievement for his career.
The benefits of relations
with the Legarans
are incalculable.
Ah, Captain Picard.
I am Ki Mendrossen,
the Ambassador's
chief of staff.
This is Sakkath,
his personal
assistant.
Has the Ambassador
been delayed?
He will be joining
us momentarily,
but first, we must
discuss some matters
of the utmost delicacy.
Please go ahead.
To be frank, Captain,
the Ambassador is
not a young man.
He tires easily.
He's going to need
a lot of rest,
to prepare himself
for the difficult job
that awaits him.
Which is why it
is imperative
that he be allowed
to conserve
his strength.
I must request
that you dispense
with any formal
activities
normally associated with
a visitor of his rank.
We had planned
a ship's concert
this evening.
I believe
that the Ambassador
is extremely fond
of Mozart.
I'm afraid it would be
impossible for him to attend.
Upon his arrival, he will be
taken directly to his quarters
where he will remain
in seclusion
until we reach Legara IV.
You have my assurance
that the Ambassador will not be
disturbed during the voyage.
That's all we ask.
Well, now that's settled.
The Ambassador is waiting.
PICARD:
Welcome aboard the Enterprise,
Ambassador Sarek.
We come to serve.
Your service
honors us.
Allow me to present
she who is my wife.
Mrs. Sarek.
Please call me
Perrin, Captain.
This is my first officer,
Commander William Riker.
Captain, would
you be so kind
as to show us
to our quarters?
SAREK:
I prefer
to view
the conference room first.
MENDROSSEN:
Ambassador, I'm sure
Sakkath and I can
handle all the
necessary details.
I will examine it for myself.
Perhaps it would be best
if we settled in first.
They worry about my health,
Captain, too much.
You will take me
to the conference room, please.
If you'll follow me, sir.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
WESLEY:
Are the Legarans
really going to sit
in this stuff?
LA FORGE:
Well, I'm sure not.
Can you believe
this smell?
What smell?
( chuckles ):
What can I say?
To us, it's a slime pit,
but, to them, it's home.
Okay, the environmental
controls are ready.
What's next?
What, are you in some kind
of a hurry or something?
Yeah, I have a date.
A date?
With who?
Ensign Dumont.
Really?
She's very attractive.
I got to admit, Wes,
though, I'm a bit surprised.
What? That she'd
go out with me?
No, that you'd actually have
the nerve to ask her.
Way to go.
The room is not ready.
No, Ambassador.
Commander La Forge
and Ensign Crusher
are still preparing...
The Legarans are
very sensitive
in matters of protocol.
You will remove
all the furniture from the room.
The walls must be bare.
I'm sure everything
will be set up
according to our
specifications
before the
Legarans arrive.
Isn't that
right, Captain?
I assure you, Ambassador,
everything will be ready
before the conference
begins.
My husband and I
have every confidence
in you, Captain.
SAREK:
I have worked
for 93 years
in preparation for this meeting.
It is vital
that no detail be overlooked.
Perhaps we should
allow these gentlemen
to return to their
work, Ambassador.
That will be acceptable.
These walls are too bright.
The way Mendrossen
described him,
I expected to see
a frail old man.
I hope I'm that frail
when I'm 202 years old.
But his aides did seem
to be a little...
overprotective,
didn't they?
From what I could see,
the Ambassador doesn't need
protection from anything.
Well, we'll respect
Mr. Mendrossen's request
and allow Ambassador
Sarek his privacy.
I suppose they were
foolish and vain--
my expectations of this voyage.
Sharing his thoughts,
memories,
his unique understanding
of the history he's made.
Does this mean you're going to
cancel the concert this evening?
No, the concert
will go ahead
as scheduled.
But it's a pity our guest
of honor will be absent.
For all we know,
the Ambassador might enjoy
an evening's
entertainment.
Why not ask his wife
if she'd like to attend?
That's an excellent
idea, Counselor.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
( door chimes )
Come in.
PICARD:
I hope I'm not intruding.
Not at all, Captain.
But Sarek is
in meditation
at the moment.
Actually, I came
to see you.
Well, how nice.
I so rarely get
visitors of my own.
Usually everyone wants
to see the Ambassador.
I find that
hard to believe.
Thank you.
These quarters are
quite comfortable.
The Ambassador and I
were very pleased
when we heard
that the negotiations
were going to take place
aboard the flagship
of the Federation.
The honor is ours.
My husband has taken
an interest in your career.
He finds it to be...
satisfactory.
My word.
High praise from a Vulcan.
Some people who expect
an emotional response
often find Vulcans
to be quite cold
when they're merely being...
Logical.
Exactly.
I came to invite you--
and your husband,
if he's available--
to a Mozart recital
this evening.
What a tempting offer.
I... doubt that the
Ambassador will be
able to attend,
but I will make it
a point to ask him.
Well then,
I hope to see you this evening.
As do I.
You are still
unable to meditate?
It is of no importance.
It has eluded you
for many weeks.
I said it is of
no importance.
You know I am right.
My wife, you will
leave me now.
I require solitude.
The temperature
in the tank
is now 150
degrees Celsius.
Okay, lock it off.
Is that it?
Can I get out
of here now?
What's your hurry?
You don't really think
anything's going to happen
with Suzanne Dumont,
do you?
At least I'm not
spending the night
with a good book,
like some people.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Just what it sounds like.
Let me tell
you something.
You'd get more action
out of a good book
than you'll ever
see on this date,
I'll guarantee it.
She's not going to waste her
time on someone like you.
Someone like me?
She's way out
of your league.
Since when did you become
an expert on women?
Compared to you, every
male on this ship
is an expert on women.
Well, at least
I don't have to find
my women in a holodeck.
What did you say?
You heard me.
Yeah, I heard you.
Just what do you think...
Something wrong?
I asked a question.
No, sir.
Nothing wrong here.
May I be excused,
Commander?
Anything you'd like
to talk about, Geordi?
No, sir.
I noticed that
Lieutenant Worf
has put Ensign
D'Amato on report
for insubordination.
D'Amato's been
an exemplary officer.
Indeed he has.
Could you look into it,
Number One?
Of course.
Good evening.
I assume that the work
is progressing
on the conference room.
Yes, I checked in
with Wesley and Geordi
a few hours ago.
There was a moment when
I actually thought
the two of them
were going to
hit each other.
Ambassador Sarek, Perrin--
on behalf of the
entire crew, welcome.
It was my wife's suggestion
that we attend.
It seemed
an ideal diversion.
Perrin can be
quite logical
when she chooses.
It seems that the Ambassador
had more free time
than I anticipated.
Commander Data will be
our featured soloist
this evening.
Data:
I have been programmed
to reproduce the individual
musical styles
of over 300 concert violinists
including Heifetz, Menuhin,
Grak-Tay, and Tataglia.
Do you have a preference?
Tataglia would be lovely.
I hope you find
the performance pleasing.
I look forward to it.
At your convenience, Mr. Data.
Please.
( playing lively chamber music )
( tempo slows )
( inaudible )
( music crescendos )
( music decrescendos )
( door closes )
Hi, Mom.
I got a message
you wanted to see me.
I thought you were
going to be at the
concert last night.
I said I may be going.
Suzanne wanted to go
to the arboretum.
Captain Picard asked me
where you were.
I don't like
making excuses for you.
Excuses?
Come on, Mom, it wasn't
an official function.
Listen, young man,
you have responsibilities
and I want you
to live up to them.
Don't you think you're
overreacting a little?
Don't talk back to me!
Okay, I won't.
Where do you think
you're going?
Away from you.
And then I just slapped him.
Really hard.
I slapped Wesley.
Do you know why
you did it?
I've never hit my son
in his life.
Beverly, this
is important.
What were you thinking
when you hit Wes?
I wasn't thinking
about anything.
I was just angry.
And Wes didn't provoke
you in any way?
It wasn't anything he
said or anything he did?
No, that's just it.
It was a sudden
burst of anger.
I still can't believe
I did it.
I don't know why
you did it either,
but I can tell you
that I've heard
the same kind of story
from ten different people
over the last two days.
This is your
command center?
Yes.
It is normally occupied
by Captain Picard,
Commander Riker,
and Counselor Troi.
Counselor Troi
is a Betazoid?
Half-Betazoid.
Her father was human.
Then she is not
a true telepath.
Her skills
are empathic in nature.
She is able to sense
the emotions of other beings.
What is Captain Picard's
background in diplomacy?
Extensive--
the Captain's first
diplomatic contact
dates back to...
And what of his knowledge
of the Legarans?
Would he be able to
conduct negotiations
with them, should
the need arise?
Do you foresee
such a circumstance occurring?
Is Ambassador Sarek unable...?
Forgive me.
I was merely exploring
various possible permutations
of our mission.
Your tour of the Bridge
has been most informative.
Excuse me.
We were sitting here.
Well, we're
sitting here now.
Come on, fella,
this is our table.
Really?
Funny, I don't see
your name on it.
Didn't your mother
teach you manners?
LA FORGE:
Hey, hey, guys...
is there some kind
of problem here?
Well, there seems
to be some question
as to whose table
this is.
Well, there are plenty
of other tables, right?
I suppose you're right.
LA FORGE:
Why don't I get everybody
another round of drinks,
all right?
I don't have to tell you
that insubordination
is a serious charge
to be filed
against any officer.
I am aware of
that, Commander.
However, Ensign D'Amato
directly challenged
my authority.
Is it my imagination
or have tempers become
a little frayed on
the ship lately?
I hadn't noticed.
( grunting and groaning )
I see what you mean.
Security to ten-forward.
Geordi, what the hell
is going on here?
I wish I knew.
All right, that's enough!
LA FORGE:
The next thing I know,
somebody's left hook
is on its way to my chin.
( sighs )
Captain, this is not
an isolated incident.
There have
been reports
of random violence
all over the ship.
Are you suggesting
this is somehow contagious?
There's no indication
of any bacteria or virus.
I've run every test I know.
I've checked the water,
food replicator,
airborne samples...
This is a hell of a time.
Well, whatever it is,
I don't want it
to affect the Ambassador.
I want his quarters isolated
from the rest of the crew
until we've
identified the cause.
It's not that
simple, Captain.
CRUSHER:
We have determined that
the outbreak of violence
started at virtually
the same time
that Sarek and his party
beamed onto the ship.
We do have a working theory.
We believe
that it's possible
that Ambassador Sarek,
himself
is responsible
for these incidents.
Sarek?
I felt something
during the concert.
Vague and undefined,
but very disturbing.
He cried.
I saw that.
I couldn't
believe it.
A Vulcan moved to
tears by music? It's...
Well, Vulcans do have
the same basic emotions we do.
They've just learned
to repress them.
What I sensed
during the concert
was that he'd lost control.
What would cause such
a loss of control?
CRUSHER:
There's a very rare condition
that sometimes affects Vulcans
over the age of 200.
Bendii Syndrome.
Its early symptoms
include
sudden bursts
of emotion
mostly irrational anger.
Eventually,
all emotional control is lost.
I can imagine nothing
that would be more offensive
to a Vulcan.
Their emotional detachment
is the very core of their being.
Why would this
affect others
onboard the ship?
Vulcans possess
telepathic abilities.
Sarek may unintentionally
be projecting intense emotions
onto other people, at random.
And when the Legarans
beam aboard?
They could very well
be affected, too.
Is there a treatment?
Can't someone else
take his place?
Sarek has built a personal
relationship with them.
They will accept no one else.
( sighs )
Well, how can we confirm
your... diagnosis?
We can grow a culture
from the tissue
of the metathalamus,
but the results
will take several days.
I have 12 hours.
That's impossible,
Captain Picard.
I cannot delay
the conference--
not for a day,
not for an hour.
The schedule itself
required three months
of negotiations.
Nevertheless, we appear to
be facing a potentially...
I give you
my word of honor
that the Ambassador
is in perfect health.
Is that enough?
Mr. Mendrossen...
You are dealing
with a theory
full of holes, Captain.
Why am I not affected
by Sarek's supposed condition?
And Perrin, how could
his wife function normally
if this theory
of yours is correct?
I cannot explain that.
Hundreds of others onboard
have not been affected either.
I have not.
It appears to be random.
Proximity, apparently, has no
bearing on this phenomenon.
You are accusing
the greatest man of his time
of losing his mind
on the eve
of his greatest triumph
and you cannot explain why.
I won't report this
to the Ambassador.
For the moment.
I don't want to divert
his attention from the mission.
But if I were you,
in the interests of your career,
I'd be very concerned
about finding the real cause
of these outbursts
before the Legarans arrive.
Mr. Data, will you please
report to my ready room?
Aye, sir.
Captain Picard
is not satisfied
with Ki Mendrossen's
assurances
that the Ambassador
is in good health.
Do you consider Sarek
capable of carrying out
his mission?
Have I given you cause
to think otherwise?
You have voiced certain
reservations to me
about his abilities.
I do not recall
making such a statement.
Not directly, no,
but you did question me
about the diplomatic
capabilities
of both Captain Picard
and Counselor Troi.
I am honor-bound
to help Sarek carry
out this mission.
That is the only
answer I can give.
Then you must decide which
is your greater obligation--
your loyalty to Sarek
or your duty
to the Federation.
Can you accept the logic
of continuing this mission?
Tell your captain...
the mission is in jeopardy.
Sakkath has been able,
until recently,
to use his telepathic skills
to reinforce
Sarek's emotional control,
thus protecting others
from the effects
of his deterioration.
He hasn't been doing
a very good job.
The strain
of this mission on Sarek
has made it impossible.
It's ironic,
isn't it?
All this magnificent
technology, we still
find ourselves
susceptible to the
ravages of old age.
( sighing ):
Loss of dignity.
The slow betrayal of our bodies
by forces we cannot master.
Do you still want to
be one of us, Data?
Sir, it is conceivable,
even for me,
that time
will eventually lead
to irreparable
circuit failure.
But there is one thing
I do not understand.
Sarek is a logical,
intelligent being.
The effects of Bendii Syndrome
are apparent.
Why would such a man
choose to ignore them?
Logic fails us sometimes, Data.
I think this is
one of those times.
I can only guess
that he does not see--
or he does not wish to see--
the truth,
and he is being insulated
against that truth
by those who love him most.
Someone has to confront him.
( sighs, clears throat )
Not a task that I'm
looking forward to.
I don't understand this.
Everyone is protecting Sarek--
his wife, Mendrossen,
even you.
What would you have me
do-- march down there
and destroy the man?
The mission with the Legarans
cannot be carried out
with Sarek
in this condition!
I know that!
Then tell him
that there is no way!
Don't you tell me what to do!
Captain, Commander...
Of course.
You're right,
Number One.
( sighs )
It's a task that
I will attend to.
Captain, I don't think
I understand
what you're telling me.
My husband is responsible
for your crew
assaulting one another?
He is very ill, Perrin.
Bendii Syndrome is
more a folk tale
than a disease.
There hasn't been
a true case of it
in my husband's lifetime.
There's one now.
Sakkath knows.
Sakkath?
Sakkath knows nothing my
husband didn't teach him.
He knows.
And more than that,
on this mission,
he has been consciously
holding Sarek's mind together
as well as he could.
That is not true.
I must see Sarek.
Captain, I know a good deal
about the Vulcan mind,
and I know a good deal
about the heart
of one particular Vulcan.
I am his wife
and he is fine.
He does not have
Bendii Syndrome,
and that shall
be the end of it.
I'm sorry.
Please.
You mustn't do
this to him.
Must not do what, my wife?
If Captain Picard
wishes to see me,
he may do so.
I regret that we have seen
so little of each other
during this voyage, Captain.
The loss is mine,
Ambassador.
Captain, may I talk
with you in private?
You were speaking
of your belief
that I suffer from
Bendii Syndrome.
I have been accused
of many things in my life.
Never an excess of emotion.
PERRIN:
Sarek...
I see no reason to
continue this discussion.
On the contrary.
I wish to assuage any fears
the Captain may have
regarding my capabilities.
I believe there is a test
for Bendii Syndrome.
I will take it immediately.
Unfortunately, the results
would not be available
for several days,
which is why I must ask
for a postponement
of the conference.
That would be a mistake.
Captain, I give you my word.
I am in perfect health.
Then...
why must Sakkath help
to contain your emotions?
Is what the Captain
says true?
No, Ambassador.
Absolutely not.
Perrin?
Were you aware
of this?
Sakkath, I await an answer.
I have been using
my limited abilities
to strengthen your
mental discipline.
Your efforts will
no longer be required.
That would not be wise.
It may not be wise,
but it is necessary.
( door opens, closes )
Leave me.
I wish to speak
with Captain Picard.
Sarek, I asked you
to reconsider.
Obey my wishes.
There is nothing to fear.
( door opens )
( door closes )
I hope I've not
embarrassed you,
Ambassador.
You seem to forget, Captain,
that I'm a Vulcan.
I'm not affected
by emotional considerations.
I think you are
affected, sir.
Far more than
you realize.
I am a logical being.
Present your arguments.
I will listen.
There is an epidemic
of violent incidents
aboard the Enterprise.
As we speak,
the situation
is worsening.
And it is your hypothesis
that I am the cause
of these incidents?
Yes.
My chief medical officer
has explored
all other probable causes.
I share your concern
for your crew.
However, you must agree
that it is not unusual
for a starship
to encounter
unexplained phenomena.
That is correct.
Therefore,
since I can assure you
that I am not the cause
of your difficulties,
the logical course would be
to have your doctor
continue the search.
She is.
It is also a fact
that these incidents began
shortly after your arrival.
Is your entire argument
to be based upon
mere coincidence?
Is it also coincidence
that your wife
and your chief of staff
are carefully isolating you?
Ah, I believe I see
the flaw in your logic.
You are reacting
to their overprotective
attitudes toward me.
They are somewhat emotional
concerning my age.
Surely, Sakkath cannot be
influenced by emotion.
Am I to be blamed for
the judgment of a child?
Sakkath is young
and inexperienced.
He erred in his assumption
that I needed help.
But you needed his help
at the concert,
or is there possibly some
other logical explanation
for what happened
that night?
What happened?
I saw you crying.
I do not cry.
I was there.
I saw the tears.
You exaggerate, Captain.
I recall only one tear.
So you were emotionally
affected by the music.
That is not possible!
You still haven't answered
my question, Sarek.
Is it logical for
a Vulcan to cry?
It was late.
I was fatigued,
nothing more.
The Legarans trust only me.
They will not meet with any
other member of the Federation.
I must be allowed
to complete my mission.
There are no other
logical solutions!
No other logical
solutions?
But, Ambassador,
there are always
other solutions.
You have said
so yourself,
many times.
What I meant was that...
Sarek of Vulcan
would never be afraid
of looking straight
at something he did
not want to see.
I warn you.
Your efforts to discredit me
will not succeed!
Sarek of Vulcan
never confused
what he wanted
with the truth.
I will not be spoken to
in this manner!
Do I hear anger
in your voice?
It would be illogical
for a Vulcan to show anger!
It would be illogical!
Illogical!
( panting )
Captain's Log, Supplemental.
In three hours' time,
we are scheduled to meet
with the Legaran delegation.
However,
it is now all too evident
that Ambassador Sarek
is in no condition
to proceed with the conference.
RIKER:
We're entering
the Legaran system, sir.
Shall I have Mr. Worf
contact their Ambassador?
No.
( sighs )
I will present
our regrets
to the Legarans
personally.
It's vital
that they understand
our reasons
for canceling
these negotiations.
Captain...
( sighs )
I think you did
the right thing.
But at what cost,
Number One?
( door chimes )
Come.
Perrin.
I must speak with you,
Captain.
I'll be on
the Bridge, sir.
How is the Ambassador?
Resting.
I've come to ask you
to reconsider
your position.
You know
that is impossible.
Sarek is a good man.
He's given the Federation
a lifetime of service.
I beg you to let him keep
the respect he has earned.
He'll never lose that respect.
Mendrossen and I never wanted
to deceive you.
My husband's condition
came on him so gradually,
it was easy for us
to delude ourselves
and pretend
that nothing was wrong.
We convinced ourselves
that he could complete
this one last task
and end his career
with dignity.
Help him, Captain.
Help him regain his pride,
his honor.
Believe me, it would
give me great pleasure,
but there is nothing I can do.
The mission can be saved...
but he needs your help to do it.
A mind-meld...
between the two of us?
Do you realize
the dangers involved
in what you are proposing,
Captain?
Yes, I do,
Ambassador,
but I also realize
the potential benefits.
We would be linked
telepathically--
sharing our thoughts
becoming, in essence,
one mind.
Which, for a few
hours, should provide
the emotional control
you need.
In that time, you can
meet with the Legarans
and conclude the treaty.
It is a generous offer,
but I must warn you
that while I would gain
your stability,
you would experience
the fierce onslaught of emotions
unleashed by my condition.
Vulcan emotions
are extremely intense.
We have learned
to suppress them.
No human could control them.
They will overwhelm you.
The mind-meld can be
a terrible intimacy.
I cannot allow it.
I'm aware of the risks,
but it is the only...
logical solution.
Your courage
honors me, Captain.
I can't say I approve of this,
Jean-Luc.
I didn't expect that
you would, Beverly.
I don't suppose
I could talk you out of it?
I'm afraid not.
Though I do admit to a
certain... trepidation.
Your... your company
is much appreciated.
( door chimes )
Come.
I see that you
are ready, Captain.
Doctor Crusher will
monitor our responses.
A sensible precaution.
My mind to your mind.
Your thoughts
to my thoughts.
Commander, the Legarans
are ready to beam aboard.
Very well.
SAREK:
Number One?
Please inform
the Legaran delegation
that Sarek of Vulcan
is on his way to welcome them.
Yes, Ambassador.
I take it the mind-meld
was a success.
Yes, all went
as planned.
Is Captain Picard
all right?
Don't worry, Number One.
And... the Ambassador?
I am myself again.
It has been a long time.
No!
It is...
it is... wrong!
It is wrong!
A lifetime of discipline
washed away
and in its place...
( chuckles )
( grunting )
bedlam.
Bedlam!
( panting )
I'm so old.
There is nothing left
but dry bones...
( voice breaking ):
Dead friends.
Oh... tired.
Oh, so tired.
It will pass,
all of it.
Just another hour or so.
You're doing fine,
just hold on.
No! This weakness disgusts me!
I hate it!
Where is my logic?
I am betrayed by...
desires.
I... oh...
I want to feel...
I want to feel
everything.
But I am a Vulcan.
I must feel nothing.
( sobbing ):
Give me back my control.
( slapping table ):
Jean-Luc!
Per...
Perrin.
Amanda...
I wanted... to give you
so much more.
I wanted to show you such...
( gasping )
tenderness.
But that is not our way.
Spock...
Amanda...
did you know...?
Perrin, can you know...
how...
( sputtering ):
much I...
love you?
I... do...
love you!
( sobbing )
Beverly...
I'm here, Jean-Luc.
I'm not going anywhere.
It's... quite difficult.
The anguish of the man.
Despair...
pouring out of him.
All those feelings.
( sobbing ):
The regrets...
I can't... stop them.
I can't stop them.
I can't. I can't.
Don't even try.
( sobbing )
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 43920.7.
Ambassador Sarek has
successfully concluded
the negotiations
with the Legarans.
The USS Merrimack
has arrived
and will transport
the Ambassador
and his party back to Vulcan.
I hope your journey
aboard the Merrimack
will be uneventful.
With the pressures
of the conference behind him,
I believe I can help him
maintain his control
until we return to Vulcan.
What will happen
to him then?
The effects
of Bendii Syndrome
are irreversible.
Medical research is always
continuing, of course.
RIKER:
Mr. O'Brien, stand by
for transport.
Aye, sir.
Thank you, Captain.
He loves you...
very much.
I know.
I've always known.
I will take my leave
of you now, Captain.
I do not think
we shall meet again.
I hope you are
wrong, Ambassador.
We shall always retain
the best part
of the other inside us.
I believe I have
the better part
of that bargain,
Ambassador.
Peace and long life.
Live long and prosper.