Captain's Log,
Stardate 43930.7.
The Enterprise
has been in attendance
at the biennial Trade
Agreements Conference
on Betazed.
For the first time,
the Ferengi are present
and I have reluctantly
consented
to their boarding
the Enterprise
for the closing reception.
( people talking, laughing )
( rhythmic music playing )
Check and mate.
WESLEY:
Perfect.
The Queen's Gambit, finished off
with the Aldabren Exchange.
Unfair.
I-I couldn't concentrate
with all that noise.
WESLEY:
Noise?
It's Algolian
ceremonial rhythms.
( snorts )
A toast to the success
of the Trade Conference,
Reittan.
I must admit...
I had some doubts
when you invited the Ferengi.
They made a profit
and behaved themselves.
What more
could one ask?
Still, they trouble me.
We Betazeds are uncomfortable
with species
like the Ferengi
whose minds we can't read.
DATA:
Perhaps your
telepathic skills
are ineffective owing
to the anomalous construction
of the Ferengi brain,
which is composed
of four different...
Thank you, Mr. Data.
It was thoughtful of you
to invite Lwaxana Troi to be
part of the Betazed
delegation.
REITTAN:
Yes, Lwaxana and I
go way back.
Her first husband and
I were old friends,
and I've known Deanna
since she was a child.
I'm sure Counselor Troi
appreciates the opportunity
to spend time
with her mother.
LWAXANA:
Little One, you could at least
pretend you're happy to see me.
Mother, we're
among non-telepaths.
It's impolite not
to speak aloud.
You mean talk
with my mouth full?
Deanna, please.
Well, all right.
You want me
to say something aloud.
Have you ever considered,
if you'd stayed on Betazed,
you might have been
a happier person?
Let's not guess
what might have been.
I love my work
on the Enterprise.
Yes, of course you do,
but it's all business
and no play.
You've got to enjoy life, relax.
Like I do.
Find yourself
the right man.
Think of your future.
Think of my future.
Lwaxana, Deanna.
Anything I can do for you?
Could I...?
She's as repulsive
as the rest of them.
Repulsive?
I find her exotic.
And what an advantage
her telepathy would be
in our negotiations.
To read our
competitors' minds.
Yes, that would
be valuable.
But she'd never agree
to use her powers
to help us.
I'm not so sure.
Lwaxana Troi of
Betazed, I believe.
I am DaiMon Tog
of the Ferengi vessel Krayton.
May I join you?
I was just
going to see
Captain Picard.
Excuse me.
Oh, Jean-Luc. Jean-Luc!
Come have a drink with me.
Tell me what you've been up to.
Perhaps later, Lwaxana.
Mr. Data and I were about
to show Reittan Grax
the, um... the, um...
the new door mechanisms
on the aft turbolifts.
If you'll excuse us.
Lwaxana Troi,
I desire you.
What?
You see, your Betazoid
skills would be
very useful to me,
and I find you
very attractive.
I am willing to pay
handsomely for you.
I don't believe this.
You must be aware
that every female has her price.
Let's get one thing
straight, little man.
I am not for sale.
And if, by some chance,
I were to become available,
I would rather eat
Orion wing-slugs than
deal with a toad-faced
troll like you!
So go away and find yourself
somebody else to become
your property.
As you wish.
Now that you've totally
humiliated us,
may we return
to our vessel?
She is exhilarating,
isn't she?
( chuckles )
And now I want her
more than ever.
Lwaxana Troi, you will be mine.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Are we at war
with the Ferengi yet?
DaiMon Tog has returned
to his vessel
and the Ferengi
have left orbit.
My mother will be relieved.
I hear she handled
the situation
quite skillfully.
An admirable woman.
I'll be sure to tell her
you said so.
LWAXANA:
Come in, Little One.
( sighs )
Mother?
Mother, please.
Oh...
Oh, after that awful
little Ferengi insulted me,
I needed to center myself.
Can you imagine
that dreadful little creature
talking to me like that?
Doesn't he realize
that I am the daughter
of the Fifth House of Betazed,
Holder of the Sacred Chalice
of Rixx?
The Sacred Chalice of Rixx
is an old clay pot
with mold growing
inside it.
Oh, well, perhaps one day,
when you're older and wiser,
you'll understand.
Come on, Little One, sit down.
Talk to me.
We spend
so little time together.
That's true.
I'm sorry, and I didn't mean
to get so upset with you
at the reception.
Oh, no.
Deanna, try to understand.
You're all I have.
My only concern
is for your happiness.
I am happy.
Why can't you believe that?
Oh, I wish I could,
but how much happiness is there
in always being there
for someone else
and never being there
for yourself?
I get a great deal
of satisfaction out of my work.
Oh, well, I'm sure you do.
I'm sure it's very rewarding
in its way, but...
( sighs )
...what about a family?
This is my family--
my friends,
here on the Enterprise.
All right, in case I have
to spell it out for you,
I am talking about finding
a husband, having a child.
That's what made me happy.
At least, until now.
Mother, look, perhaps
someday I will marry,
but you have to let me
make my own choices,
live my own life,
and not the life
that you would
choose for me.
You had your chance
with Commander Riker.
Look how you ruined that.
I did not ruin anything.
We've become
very good friends.
Well, all the better.
You certainly wouldn't want
to marry an enemy.
I see we can't talk
about this.
Very well, have it your own way,
Little One.
Little One?!
You called me that
when I was five.
Now stop demeaning me
and address me as an adult.
I'll be home on Betazed
if you need me, Little...
Deanna.
Adding preprocessors
to the neutrino counters
boosted efficiency by 11%.
Of course, Commander La Forge
and Commander Data
did most of the work...
Not so fast, Wesley.
Reprocessing the data
with an optical chip
was your idea.
That is correct, sir.
Although Commander La Forge
and I designed the chip,
Mr. Crusher derived the equation
governing its operation.
The point is, you completed the
upgrade well ahead of schedule.
Very impressive.
Indeed. Fine work.
We shall miss you,
Mr. Crusher.
As you've guessed, final
entrance examination scores
from Starfleet Academy
have arrived.
Congratulations.
As soon as you have
completed the oral exam,
you'll be formally admitted.
We'll have you
back at Betazed
in plenty of time
to meet up with the
Academy transport ship.
Thank you, sir.
That'll be all.
Number One, a moment.
Yes, Captain?
You'll agree that this is a
fairly routine mapping mission?
Yes, sir.
Counselor Troi
had the good sense
to ask for shore leave.
I can see I'm going to have
to suggest it to you.
Have a good time, Number One.
( indistinct conversation )
( Deanna laughing )
RIKER:
...your mother.
I think it's around here
somewhere.
Well, maybe it died.
It has been a few years.
Muktok live
for hundreds of years.
Here it is.
Oh!
Oh... oh, it's lovely.
( musical tinkling )
I remember that sound
and all the good times we had.
I remember a certain
junior officer
meeting a very serious
psychology student.
The best part about
being assigned to Betazed.
LWAXANA:
Ah, this is the perfect spot.
Put the food down
over there, Mr. Homn.
Oh, isn't it a beautiful day
for a picnic?
( sighing )
Oh, they'll be joining us
in a moment.
No, no, not that.
Here, I-I-I...
Put the food over there.
No, no, you can
go back...
Mother, how did you know
about this place?
Your father used
to bring me here.
Sit down.
RIKER:
And you even brought provisions.
Very thoughtful.
Here, Will, Deanna.
Try an oskoid.
They're delicious.
You see, that sap
running through the veins
helps keep it warm.
Very tasty.
So, tell us, Lwaxana,
the last time we met,
you were looking
for a husband.
Have you had any luck?
Alas, no, but what happens to me
isn't important.
I am much more concerned
with other people
getting on with their lives.
Mother.
Mr. Homn,
I noticed some uttaberries
back along the path.
Pick some.
Well, Mr. Homn and I
could go back home
if you two
would like to be alone.
It's, uh,
such a romantic setting.
Mother, stop it!
Darling, you have been
so excitable lately.
Have you ever thought
of a leave of absence?
I could talk
to Jean-Luc.
Try the oskoid.
Very different.
( hum of an active transport)
What the...?
Oh.
For one whose beauty surpasses
even these pericules.
DaiMon Tog,
I thought the Krayton
left orbit hours ago.
It did.
But when I tried to get
the image of Lwaxana Troi
out of my mind,
I could not succeed.
This is ludicrous.
You mean, you came all the way
back to Betazed for me?
Why continue to search
for perfection
once you have
found it?
I don't believe this.
Now, look, demon Tog
or whatever
you call yourself,
I am the daughter
of the Fifth House,
Holder of
the Scared Chalice of Rixx,
Heir to the Holy Rings
of Betazed,
and unless you want to create
an interstellar incident,
you had better
beam back to your ship.
Returning to my ship
is exactly what I had in mind.
Krayton, transport four
immediately.
No, Tog...
FERENGI:
Pawn takes Knight,
King's Level.
( chuckling )
FERENGI 2:
Bishop takes Knight,
King's Level.
Rook to Queen Four.
( groans )
( Ferengi chuckling )
Lwaxana?
Oh...
Deanna?
Where are we?
From the smell
of things
I'd say we're aboard
a Ferengi vessel.
The Ferengi can't do that.
You're Starfleet officers.
Well, Tog must not
have read that chapter
in the Ferengi
Book of Etiquette.
Enterprise?
Must be too far
out of range.
Oh...
( yelps )
( both gasp )
DaiMon, they have
regained consciousness.
Very good.
( gasps )
I should have known.
Even their transporters
can't be trusted.
Why have you removed
our clothing?
Females do not deserve
the honor of clothing.
They're as bad as humans.
Look at that leer
on his face.
No, his is an expression
of revulsion,
but it is a feeling that
I do not share, Lwaxana.
Oh, uh...
Well, it's cold in here.
Do you want me to become ill?
You must forgive the Doctor.
He is not accustomed to dealing
with Betazoid females.
Now, Lwaxana,
I have a, uh,
business proposition for you.
Thanks, but I'm not interested
in any of your propositions.
Hear me out.
Your telepathic powers could
bring us both great profit.
Huh. Why would I want
to bring you profit?
In order to keep your daughter
alive and healthy, for one.
TOG:
There is no need for threats.
Lwaxana is a sensible female.
I don't like the sound of this,
Mother.
I believe I can control him,
Little One.
I'm sure that, uh...
we can talk about this.
Just the two of us.
A wise choice.
Farek, leave us.
Wel...
And you may rejoin
your friend.
Mother, are you sure?
I'll be fine.
( console beeps )
Mm.
( chuckles nervously )
And now, Lwaxana Troi...
let us talk.
15 hours from Gamma Erandi
and already the subspace static
is playing hell
with the communications.
Just what you'd expect
from a stellar nursery.
Wesley, congratulations
on passing your Starfleet
written examination.
An excellent achievement.
Thanks, Data.
Now, if I can just do as
well on the oral exams.
Not to worry, you will.
And when you return,
we'll be gaining the best ensign
in the fleet.
There is no guarantee
that Wesley will be reassigned
to the Enterprise.
91% of Starfleet graduates
are not posted
to Galaxy-class starships
on their first assignment.
I never thought of that.
I always assumed I'd be
coming back to the Enterprise.
Well, I'm sure Captain Picard
will request you.
That is, if he's still
commanding the Enterprise
when you graduate.
I never thought of that either.
I never thought
I'd feel this way
about leaving you guys
and the Enterprise.
Is that not part
of the human experience?
Growth and change?
Well, I suppose so, but...
Listen, Wesley,
I felt the same way
when I left my family
to go to the Academy,
but it was one
of the best times of my life.
You're going to meet new friends
and have adventures
that you can't
even imagine yet.
I hope you're right, Geordi.
LWAXANA:
Oh, Little One,
Tog's given me something
perfectly hideous to wear.
He says it flatters my beauty.
( chuckles )
So far, Mother's
in no danger.
I hope she knows
what she's doing.
Well, she's bought us
some time.
Let's make the most of it.
I wouldn't do that.
I don't need your help.
The hell you don't.
You're two moves away
from being mated.
( growls )
See? You should have
listened to me.
Now you've only got
one possible escape...
( grunts )
That wasn't it.
( laughs )
You should have moved
the bishop.
Ridiculous!
The bishop was pinned.
Don't listen to me.
Forget the fact
that I beat you in 30 moves.
Pure luck.
I was being polite.
I could have won in 20.
Then prove it.
Pawn to Queen Four,
King's Level.
Pawn to King's Bishop Three,
Queen's Level.
I must admit, when you, uh,
first approached me
aboard the Enterprise,
I was... intrigued.
( chuckles ):
You mean revolted.
Perhaps a little.
Do you forgive me?
Yes.
But with your powers,
we could be a
formidable team.
My, you have great strength
in your hands.
And you like that?
( sighs ):
I have always admired
strong males.
You are beautiful.
It is impossible
for me to resist you.
Then, uh... don't.
Initial scans of ionization
patterns complete, sir.
Now correlating sensor readings.
It's almost
incomprehensible--
the amount of energy
being expended.
Actually, it is 5.34 times
ten to the 41st watt, sir.
Well within the norm for
this type of phenomenon.
Yes, yes, yes, perhaps, Data.
But that takes away
none of the wonder.
Check.
I'm sick of this game.
Of course, now that
you are losing.
Who's losing?
I'm just tired of standing up.
You can't resign now.
It's hard to play from in here.
I can't even see
the whole board.
Ah.
Then you'll finish the game
if I let you
out of the cell?
I might.
( laughs )
Clever, human,
but I'm not that foolish.
What, do you think
I'm going to try to escape?
What would that get me?
You've already got her.
Besides, where would I go?
I do not trust you.
Fine.
Thanks for the game.
Come out here.
Now save your
rook, if you can.
...and that was
my first husband.
Not much
of a conversationalist
but, uh... what a lover.
Well, then I met...
I do not want to hear
about your other romances.
It makes me jealous.
My, my, what, uh...
big ears you have.
Has anyone ever told you
how attractive they are?
Some females
think they are my best feature.
No one has ever given me
oo-mox like this before.
Oo-mox?
There's no translation,
but the ear is
one of our most
erogenous zones.
Those Ferengi
have iron jaws.
LWAXANA:
Little One, if Tog were
a kitten, he'd be purring.
Good work, Mother.
According to Mother,
DaiMon Tog is extremely
relaxed at the moment.
Tell Lwaxana
to keep him relaxed
while we call in the cavalry.
COMPUTER:
Access to communications denied.
All transmissions
to be authorized by DaiMon Tog.
Let's see just how
relaxed DaiMon Tog is.
Mother, we're out of the cell
and we're trying
to contact the Enterprise,
but we can't do it
without Tog's access code.
Do you think
you could manage to...
LWAXANA:
Say no more, Little One.
Lwaxana, you and I are going
to make such a wonderful team.
With your telepathy
and my cunning, I foresee...
A very profitable future.
( chuckles in agreement )
Subspace interference
is subsiding, sir.
Communications
have been restored.
Good.
Contact Commander Riker
on Betazed.
Message coming in
from Betazed, sir.
Priority one.
On screen.
Captain Picard, at last.
We have been trying to reach you
for two days.
Our communications have been
blocked by the nebula, Reittan.
Is there a problem?
I'm afraid so, Captain.
Lwaxana, Deanna,
and Commander Riker
have disappeared.
I knew I wanted you
the moment I saw you.
You have fulfilled
all of my expectations.
How sweet.
Farek thought
it was a bad idea,
but I knew better.
How clever.
I knew best.
I always know best.
( low voice ):
How repugnant.
What?
Oh, I said, "How romantic."
I can't
resist a man
who knows what he wants
and goes after it.
That's me and that's why
I am DaiMon of this ship.
I take charge
in every situation.
More to the left, woman.
Whatever you say.
( moaning happily )
My darling, would you care
for something to drink?
Mmm. You're so attentive.
Does your food
synthesizer
know how to make
an Arcturian Fizz?
I don't think so.
They have certain
pleasure-enhancing qualities.
Hmm.
Uh... let me teach
your computer
how to make one.
Oh!
I'll need your access code.
Yes, my beloved.
Computer, access code Keh-ee
Yoor-ee Dah-teh-ee...
Tog, be silent!
I knew you were
not to be trusted.
Doctor Farek, I was
just going to make
DaiMon Tog a drink.
Save your lies
for this fool.
B-But he's...
But, oh, please,
don't listen to him, don't.
No, he's misunderstood.
No, Tog.
You have
misunderstood.
You have been tricked
by a sly female
who finds you repulsive.
She was only trying
to serve me a drink.
You almost gave her
complete access
to the ship's computer--
a security breach
severe enough
to cost you
your command.
It's time you took my advice.
Let me study her.
Study her?
Your mind probes
could kill her.
You brought her aboard
for her telepathic powers.
If I can determine
what neural configuration
gives her those powers,
I may be able
to duplicate them.
We could still profit from this.
I don't know.
A true DaiMon would not
be blinded by lust.
Give her to me
or I may be forced
to report your transgressions.
Very well.
Oh...
Take her.
WORF:
When you're finished here,
survey in that direction.
Aye, sir.
I wish I had some answers
for you, Lieutenant Worf.
Mr. Homn was no help?
None. He last saw them
as he was leaving
this clearing.
When he returned, all
three of them were gone.
Lieutenant Foley discovered this
in the pond.
The species is Zan Periculi.
It is not indigenous to Betazed
but to Lappa IV,
a Ferengi world.
Now we have a reasonable
hypothesis as to whom.
The difficult
question is where.
The Ferengi ship is almost
as fast as the Enterprise.
She could be anywhere by now.
Commander Riker will assume
we'll be searching for them.
He'll find some way
to send us a message.
Mr. Worf,
I want continual
monitoring
of Ferengi
subspace frequencies.
Mr. La Forge, can you extend
our sensor range?
If I narrow the band and tie in
the long-range sensors
to the subspace scanners,
I can boost the gain.
Make it so.
Do you wish to leave orbit, sir?
Not until we have
some place to go.
( sighs )
I've done everything I know how.
It's no use.
Without Tog's security code,
I can't get near
their communication system.
We're running
out of time.
Farek's about to begin
the neural scan on Mother.
Maybe I'm going about this
in the wrong way.
If I pick a minor subsystem,
something non-essential...
Like this-- warp field
phase adjustment.
All this does is suppress
the subspace interference
generated
by the warp engines.
Meaning what?
Meaning, if I set up
a simple oscillation,
I can send out a signal.
The trick is
to create a message
the Enterprise will understand
but the Ferengi will think is
just normal subspace static.
( electronic zapping )
( Lwaxana groaning )
( Lwaxana yells )
Oh...
What's wrong?
Mother.
Will... we have to help her.
Thanks for your help, Wes,
but you'd better get
aboard the Bradbury.
They were ready to break
orbit an hour ago.
As soon as I'm sure
this works.
Initiating scans now, Captain.
( static hissing and beeping)
Can you locate the Krayton?
Ferengi transmissions
are routinely scrambled
and encoded, sir.
Without breaking the
code, we will be unable
to identify
any specific
Ferengi vessel.
Ferengi codes are damn near
impossible to break.
Gentlemen, I have
the utmost confidence
in your ability to
perform the impossible.
( static popping and beeping)
Captain, the Bradbury
is hailing us.
They can no longer delay
their departure.
Mr. Crusher,
now.
No lengthy farewells.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
DATA:
The repetitive nature
of the subcarrier pattern
implies a modified
Huffman-Greenlaw encoder
scheme...
Deck six.
Wesley.
Take care.
You too, Mom.
Something the matter?
We've been scanning
Ferengi transmissions
trying to locate the Krayton.
One of the signals was...
I don't know, familiar somehow.
Something in the message?
No, the message was scrambled.
It was the static!
Where are you going?
( door opens and closes )
Captain.
The Bradbury has informed us
they can no longer wait
for Mr. Crusher to come aboard.
Wesley.
Captain, I think
there's a pattern
to the subspace
interference
I heard in one
of the Ferengi messages.
Wesley, unless you
leave immediately,
you're going to miss
the Bradbury.
The interference itself
could be a message.
If I could just hear a replay
of the subspace scans.
Signal the Bradbury
they may leave.
Play back
the Ferengi transmissions.
( static hissing and popping)
Wait, repeat that one.
Put it on continuous replay.
Hear that popping noise?
Data, can you filter out
everything but that sound?
( popping, rhythmic beeps )
That's Cochrane distortion--
a fluctuation in the phase
of the subspace field.
All warp engines generate
that kind of interference.
But listen to the pattern.
It's the Algolian
ceremonial rhythm
that the musician played
at the reception.
Mr. Crusher
is correct, sir.
There is a temporal
correlation.
Then it is a signal
from Commander Riker.
Ingenious.
He selected a signal
we'd recognize
but one the Ferengi
would dismiss as static.
( console beeping )
WORF:
Signal source located, Captain.
Plot an intercept course.
Course plotted and laid in,
sir.
Well done, Mr. Crusher.
Warp eight.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
( groaning loudly )
Get away from her.
What do you think
you're doing?
Standoff, Commander.
DaiMon Tog, can't we
strike a bargain?
All I am concerned about
is my daughter's safety.
What happens to me
isn't important.
What are you suggesting?
Well, let me be candid,
DaiMon Tog.
Deanna's of no use to you.
She's only
half Betazoid.
And if you keep Riker,
Starfleet will never stop
chasing you.
Release them.
Release them and I will stay
with you willingly.
I'll even use
my telepathy
to aid in your negotiations.
A tempting offer.
I would like to believe you.
The offer is genuine.
I give you my word as a daughter
of the Fifth House of Betazed.
Lwaxana, don't.
I've made up my mind.
I can't let you do this.
William, I am a grown woman.
I can make my own decisions.
Mother, we can't
just leave you here.
Yes, you can.
And before he
changes his mind.
Please, Little One,
do this for me.
Just this once.
Do we have an agreement?
I give you my word.
I will release your daughter
and the Commander.
CREWMAN:
DaiMon, a Federation ship
approaching at high warp.
The Enterprise has found us.
Slow to impulse.
Raise shields.
Inform the Enterprise
that two of our guests
are ready to return.
The other will be
staying with us
at her own request.
I must protest, DaiMon.
Lwaxana has given her word.
Oo-mox is only the beginning.
Are you both all right?
None the worse for wear.
My mother bought
our freedom, Captain.
She doesn't want
to stay with Tog.
Hail the Krayton.
Frequencies open.
DaiMon Tog responding.
On screen.
Captain Picard, so good of you
to meet us.
We were on our way to Betazed
to return our guests.
Of course you were, DaiMon.
But you're still holding
Lwaxana Troi.
When will you get it
through your thick head
that it's over
between us, Jean-Luc?
I think I know
what she's doing.
You have to fight
to get her
back, Captain.
Open.
Um, uh, uh... it's not over
between us, Lwaxana.
Um, uh...
you're mine and, um...
I-I will not let you go.
I-I insist you
return to my side
immediately.
You mean, you
still care?
"My love is a fever,
longing still for that
which longer nurseth
the disease."
Tell me more.
"In faith, I do not love thee
with mine eyes,
"for they in thee
a thousand errors see,
"But 'tis my heart
that loves what they despise,
"Who, in despite of view,
art pleas'd to dote.
"Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?
Thou art more lovely
and more temperate..."
You didn't tell me that you
and Captain Picard were...
You said you didn't
want to hear about
my other romances.
I have a new love, Jean-Luc.
And you can't
keep killing all my lovers.
Now, that simply has to stop.
Killing?
Oh, he's insanely jealous.
Listen, Tog,
I must possess Lwaxana,
and if that means destroying
your ship in the process,
so be it.
Captain, I had
no idea Lwaxa...
Don't let him
threaten you.
You can defeat him.
The only way you'll
ever get me back
is over Tog's dead body.
That can be arranged.
Mr. Worf, arm phaser banks
and photon torpedoes.
If Lwaxana Troi is not
in my arms in ten seconds,
throw everything you've got
at the Krayton.
But you will destroy Lwaxana.
"When I have pluck'd the rose,
"I cannot give it
vital growth again.
It needs must wither."
Nine, eight...
"'Tis better to have loved
and lost
than never to have loved
at all."
Seven... six...
No, wait.
Five... four...
Beam her to their Bridge now.
Two... one...
You wonderfully
jealous fool, you.
TOG:
Captain...
I-I trust there will be
no further action
taken against us?
Such as my reporting this
incident to your superiors
who may question
your competence as DaiMon?
I will think about it.
Screen off.
Thank you, Jean-Luc.
You were most convincing.
You certainly
convinced me.
I am truly grateful,
Mrs. Troi,
that you risked your life
to save my people.
I'll have you home
in a few hours.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
That won't be necessary.
I'd just love
to hear more
of your poetry.
Ah...
Perhaps another time.
Please.
Mr. Crusher.
Set course for Betazed.
( quietly ):
Warp nine.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
I've been in touch with Admiral
Hahn at Starfleet Academy.
He regrets your missing
the oral examination
but hopes that you will
reapply next year.
I understand, sir.
And I do intend to reapply.
In the interim,
the Academy's loss is our gain.
The Enterprise
will continue to benefit
from your talents
for another year.
Thank you, sir.
( inhales deeply )
Is that all?
No.
Is there something wrong,
Captain?
I'm just thinking that...
I'm saying good-bye to you
as you are today.
But I thought you said I
wasn't going to be able to go.
The Academy must make you wait,
that's true.
But when I review your service
to this ship, your crew mates,
I cannot in all conscience
make you wait
for the Academy.
You see, Wesley...
in my eyes, you're an
acting Ensign in title only.
I hereby grant you
field promotion to full Ensign
with all the commensurate
responsibilities
and privileges
of that rank.
Congratulations.
You're dismissed.
Lwaxana Troi has beamed down
to Betazed, Captain.
Notify Starfleet we are en route
to the Xanthras system
for our rendezvous
with the Zapata.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Crusher,
take us out of orbit.
Set a course for Xanthras III.
Warp factor six.
Aye, sir.
Course is set.
Engage.