Captain's Log,
Stardate 43957.2.
We are charting
an unexplored star system
within the Zeta Gelis Cluster.
This routine assignment
has made
for a refreshingly quiet time
aboard the Enterprise.
That's her.
WORF:
Which one?
LA FORGE:
The one on the right.
Don't stare.
Why not?
Because she'll see.
Good.
You must let her see
the fire in your eyes.
But what would I say?
Words come later.
It is the scent
that first speaks of love.
Thanks, Worf.
That helps a lot.
Hi, Geordi.
( clears throat )
Hi.
So, how have you been?
Good, uh...
( sighs )
How are things
down in Engineering?
Fine, they...
( growls softly )
They-- they've been fine.
Well, I'll see you around.
( sighs )
I have much to teach you
about women.
RIKER:
Mr. La Forge, report
to Transporter Room Three.
What's this all
about, Commander?
Sensors have discovered
a small one-man spaceship
crashed on the planet.
We've picked up
life-signs--
humanoid, very faint and fading.
Radiation levels
within acceptable limits.
LA FORGE:
We can beam him out
from under there.
Get him right up
to Sick Bay.
He's not stable enough
for transport.
There's damage
to his brain stem.
Autonomic functions are failing.
His heart needs
active neural feedback.
It can't regulate itself.
I need a volunteer.
Right here.
I'm going to hook up
your nervous systems
through the tricorder.
Your brain will
regulate both systems.
That should stabilize
him long enough
to get him
up to the ship.
Take deep, regular breaths.
If anything goes wrong,
I'll break
the connection.
Okay.
( gasps )
Geordi.
I'm fine. No problem.
Transporter Room, three to
beam directly to Sick Bay.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Autonomic responses
are still low.
Begin cardiostimulation.
60 cc's of inaprovaline.
Massive infection is setting in.
Use the protodynoplaser
to stabilize his immune system.
We need to design a virus
that can infiltrate
his cell structure
and boost his ATP production.
NURSE TEMPLE:
What about Commander La Forge?
He's waiting
in the diagnostic center.
I need you to give him
a full bio-scan.
See if there's
any residual effect
from that energy discharge
during the neurolink.
Keep his arm
in cryogenic stasis
until the vital signs
are strong enough
for surgical procedures.
From the size and shape
of the wreckage,
it appeared to be
some kind of an escape pod.
Their control system
was badly damaged,
which is probably
what caused the crash.
An escape pod?
Then he couldn't
have traveled very far.
Mr. Data, are there any other
signs of ships in the area?
I am picking up
a scattering of debris
in extended orbit
around the planet.
It reads as refined metals
and other synthetic compounds.
The remains of
a larger vessel.
He must have
left in the pod
before the ship
was destroyed.
Sensors show trace elements
in the debris
that would indicate phaser fire
was recently exchanged.
Were you able to
salvage anything else
from the escape pod?
This is all that was left
from their
computer system.
Mr. Data,
can you access it?
It will take time, sir.
Downloading this into our system
will require fabrication
of a matrix translator
to emulate
the alien's computer system.
Keep me apprised
of your progress.
Aye, sir.
Limb re-fusion appears
to be successful, Doctor.
Tissue oxygenation
is within norms.
Hmm. That's all
we can do for now.
We won't be
able to test
neuromuscular function
for a few days.
( door opens )
Ah, Geordi.
Can I go now, Doc?
No need to keep you here,
your bio-scan
came out negative.
Could have told you that.
I feel great.
How's your patient?
( sighs )
I never thought
he'd make it this far.
There was major trauma to
his head and chest cavity,
massive plasma loss and severe
damage to most of his organs.
What are his chances?
I believe he's
going to live.
I'm afraid I can't take
the credit for it, though.
His body seems to have
amazing recuperative powers.
The damaged tissue seems
to be repairing itself
at a phenomenal rate.
There's one thing
that troubles me, though.
What's that?
Take a look at this.
Cell regeneration.
Yes.
The thing is, it has nothing
to do with the injuries.
These are undamaged cells
that seem to be mutating.
Do you have a theory
as to the cause?
No, I've never seen anything
like it in my life.
There is a possibility
that it's part of his
natural healing process.
I hope it is,
because there's nothing
I can do to stop it.
I'm telling you, Data,
there's got to be some way
to decode the information
in this thing.
I agree, Geordi, but the data
matrix within the capsule
does not correspond
to any standard format.
All we have been
able to determine
is that the device contains
a chemically-based system
for molecular energy encoding.
Yeah, and the computer
still can't analyze
the specific chemical
elements involved.
It's gotta be part of the
data processing system.
What if... it's a feedback
loop controller?
The compact shape does suggest
a rapid chemical processing
and storage capacity.
We found it
near the escape pod's
instrumentation assemblage.
This capsule might process
the ship's dynamic motions
and augment its manual
control inputs.
You know, we could
send it a few test signals.
Make it think
the entire assemblage
was awake and operating.
An intriguing experiment.
The capsule might provide us
with information
without the need to decode
the storage medium itself.
Perhaps we should examine
your theory immediately.
WORF:
Less talk.
More synthehol.
We came here to relax.
I am relaxed.
In fact, I've never felt better.
But you know, Worf,
you're right.
The storage capsule
can wait awhile.
See you, Patti.
Christy, you're not
leaving, are you?
I was just on my way
down to the arboretum.
Mmm, would you care
for some company?
I'd love some,
but I didn't think
you were interested
in that kind of thing.
Mmm, there are a
lot of things
that you don't
know about me.
( door opens and closes )
I've been tutoring him.
He learns very quickly.
CRUSHER:
Medical Log, Stardate 43958.8.
I have removed patient
"John Doe"
from the emergency
bio-support unit.
In just 36 hours, most of
his major organ systems
have regenerated themselves
to the point where they can
now function on their own.
( gasps )
( sighs )
I am... alive.
You certainly are.
Thank you for my life.
Tell me...
who am I?
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43960.6.
Our mission to map
the Zeta Gelis Star Cluster
is proceeding on schedule.
Meanwhile, Dr. Crusher reports
that the recovery of the
patient she has named John Doe
continues at a remarkable pace.
Are you experiencing
any discomfort?
None.
I can feel the life
returning to my body.
Your neurofibrowaves
are functioning
almost normally again.
That puts you about six weeks
ahead of my original schedule.
That should give you
and your colleagues
something to talk about.
You are all
we've talked about
since your arrival.
I believe I'm ready for the
next phase of my treatment.
You are right.
It is about time
you stopped taking up
valuable bed space.
Now, these motor-assist
bands will provide you
with electrical stimulation
for your arms and legs.
They will help you
to relearn
how to control
your muscles again.
But remember, you've been off
your feet for almost a month.
So, don't be disappointed
if at first your mobility
is restricted.
Your limbs are still weak.
I appreciate your
concern, Doctor,
but I think I may
surprise you again.
I feel strong enough to fly.
Whoa.
Perhaps I should concentrate
on walking first.
Let's try it again, but a
little more slowly this time.
Much more slowly.
I envy your
reflexes, Captain.
I envy your strength of will.
Dr. Crusher has been keeping me
informed of your progress.
It's really quite extraordinary.
I have an
extraordinary doctor.
Oh...
She gave me
back my life.
I hope that I am worthy
of her efforts.
Are you still unable to recall
anything about your past?
Unfortunately,
Captain,
my memories begin the moment
I woke up in Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher told me you think
I was in some kind of battle.
PICARD: We're quite
sure of that.
Have you any idea
how you came to be
in that escape pod,
or what happened
to the ship?
No.
Believe me, Captain,
it's a horrible feeling
not knowing who you are,
where you're from.
Have you tried
synaptic induction?
His neural nets don't conform
to any known patterns.
Conventional neurotherapy
has proven ineffective.
Hopefully, in time,
his memory pathways
will reestablish
themselves naturally.
That same pain?
Yes.
I think I've made
enough progress for one day.
Not a relapse, I hope.
This has nothing to do
with his previous wounds.
I think this has
something to do
with the continuing mutation
of his cell structure.
And you still have no theory
as to what's causing it?
It doesn't make any sense.
I seem to be
a mystery, Doctor.
To you...
and to myself.
( clears throat )
Well, this is where I get off.
See you tonight
in Ten-Forward?
Yeah, I'll be there.
Hello, Commander.
Miss Henshaw.
Bridge.
Deck six.
So, you and Miss Henshaw
have been seeing
a lot of each other.
Every night this week.
Is that all?
I thought you'd been walking
around with that smile
on your face a lot
longer than that.
Well, I guess I have.
This whole last month or so,
everything seems
to be going my way.
I don't know what it is,
but something
sure has
changed around here.
The only thing
that's changed is you.
Me?
I'm the same old
guy I always was.
If you say so.
I don't remember
the old Geordi having
that much success with
Miss Christy Henshaw.
( chuckles )
Well, maybe I am
a little bit more confident
than I used to be.
What happened to you?
I was kayaking in
the holodeck again.
You dislocated
your shoulder.
Sit down, I'll get the
osteotractor frame.
Hi, Mom.
We still on
for dinner tonight?
7:30 sharp.
I'll be right back.
( whimpers in pain )
Kayaking again?
Yeah.
How's my mom's
favorite patient?
Judge for yourself.
Not bad.
Your mom promised me
a tour of the ship tomorrow.
You may find this hard
to believe, but Sick Bay
can be an incredibly
boring place to be.
O'BRIEN:
Hey, Doc!
I'm dying out here.
Don't worry, my friend.
You'll be all right.
The pain's gone.
It's completely healed.
I don't understand.
What did you do?
I don't know.
It was instinct.
I just touched him.
I've run every test and scan
on him that I can think of.
And yet, there's
no physiological evidence
to indicate that he would
possess such powers.
But then, there's so much
about John that's a mystery.
You know,
I really like him.
He does have a certain charm,
doesn't he?
The entire medical staff
has commented on it.
You seem a little taken
with him yourself.
He has a strength and serenity
that I find very attractive.
And yet,
he's vulnerable.
I guess I find him...
intriguing.
Seems like there's a little
more to it than that.
Is this your way of asking me
if I'm getting
romantically involved with him?
You said it, I didn't.
My feelings towards him
aren't romantic...
exactly.
I mean, I know that
the doctor-patient relationship
can sometimes create
a false sense of intimacy,
but this... is different.
There's an almost
spiritual connection.
( sighs )
I guess I'm not making
any sense, am I?
I think I understand.
Data, I was thinking about
the storage capsule last night,
and I was wondering.
What if we've been going
about this thing the wrong way?
We've been trying to analyze
its mechanical properties.
What if it's a biochemical
storage medium?
Are you suggesting
that it employs
memory RNA, like
an organic cell?
Well, it does contain
quantities of nucleic acids.
Perhaps the information
sequences are encoded
in the molecular
patterns themselves.
Computer, scan
the storage capsule.
Analyze molecular sequences
on nucleic acid chains.
Well, what do you know?
A navigational chart.
It appears that your hypothesis
was correct, Geordi.
I knew it.
Captain!
You found something?
We've determined that
the storage capsule
from John Doe's
escape pod
contains navigational
information.
Can you match these stars
to our charts?
Computer, run transformational
matrix calculations.
Match navigational referents
to known stars in this sector.
COMPUTER: Information on
this sector is incomplete.
No correlation.
I'm not giving up yet,
not after coming so close
to cracking this thing.
You know, that might be
flight path information
from John's ship, but without
a frame of reference,
I can't determine
its origin points.
Computer, assume those paths
are course corrections
and derive
gravitational values
for stellar objects near
those flight paths.
Most of these are
ordinary G-type stars.
This would appear to be
a neutron star,
possibly a pulsar.
LA FORGE:
Which means that this
might be a rotational
time reference.
Computer, assume these symbols
are pulsars.
Translate associated values
into standard
temporal notations.
Computer, is there a pulsar
with a rotational period
of 1.5244 seconds
within sensor range?
COMPUTER:
Affirmative.
Bingo!
Now, Computer,
overlay navigational chart
using referenced pulsars
and project a flight path
back to its origin.
COMPUTER:
Flight path originated
at bearing 003, mark 015.
Distance, 2.3 parsecs.
That's it, Captain.
That's where John Doe
came from.
That bearing is almost directly
along our planned course, sir.
Good. Then, we can
continue our mission
without significant
interruption.
Home?
PICARD: Yes.
Using the information
we found in your escape pod,
we may be able to return
you to your people.
I cannot go back.
Why is that?
You must not take
me home, Captain.
CRUSHER:
John?
Your memory--
has it returned?
All I know is that
we came out here to escape.
Escape?
There were others with you?
Yes, I was not alone.
But what happened to the others,
or what we were escaping from,
I cannot remember.
But I do know
you must not take me back.
Not yet!
We'll not arrive
in your star system
for at least three weeks.
That will give us plenty of
time to discuss this further.
Hopefully, by then,
you will have regained
more of your memory.
You're right.
Of course, Captain.
I apologize for my outburst.
It's...
it's understandable.
( door opens and closes )
( gasps )
( conversation and laughter )
This ship is astounding.
It seems to stretch on
without end.
We can see the rest
of it some other time.
This is your first day
out of Sick Bay,
and I don't want you
to overexert yourself.
This looks like
an ideal place to rest.
My thoughts exactly.
Truly remarkable.
What is?
These people.
They're all so different
from one another,
and yet, they work
together freely.
That surprises you?
It is... new to me.
My people are different somehow.
If only I could remember.
Yesterday...
for one... terrifying moment,
there was clarity.
You mean, the energy pulse?
Yes.
For that moment,
my purpose seemed clear.
And then it was gone.
The pain... the energy pulse...
must be linked to the cell
mutation in the body.
Oh, I wish I could
help you find the truth.
Beverly, you've done
so much for me.
I only wish there was some way
I could repay you.
But you have.
The friendship we've developed
has made me very happy.
The rapport
that exists between us
also means a great deal to me.
But... I am on some
kind of a journey.
Whatever brought me here...
whatever is happening
to my body,
is all part of that journey.
And I must complete it...
before...
any other consideration.
( console beeping )
Sir, I am reading a vessel
on long-range scanners.
It is coming from Sector 9569.
What configuration?
Impossible to identify
at this distance.
However, it is
on an intercept course.
Captain, the ship is
traveling at warp 9.72.
Warp 9.72?
Time till intercept?
At present course and speed,
ten hours, 53 minutes.
Try and hail them, Mr. Worf.
No response, Captain.
Keep monitoring their approach.
Repeat the hail
every half an hour.
Aye, sir.
Whoever they are, they're
in a big hurry to get here.
( alarm beeping )
Dr. Crusher, medical emergency,
room four.
( labored breathing )
I can't make it stop.
John, tell me, is it
worse than before?
Much worse.
Should I get something
for the pain?
No, the readings are
fluctuating too wildly.
Besides, it wouldn't
do any good.
His entire cell structure
is transforming.
I have to leave, Beverly.
John, where do
you have to go?
I must get off this ship.
That's impossible.
Not in your condition.
I must!
Security.
Okay, let's realign
the magnetic inducer
on the starboard nacelle.
( groaning )
John.
Leave the control booth
immediately!
( alarm sounding )
John, listen to me.
You must come down.
I'll try to help you.
Step away from
the controls.
Get back.
Please, stay away.
I have no wish to harm you,
but you must return
to Sick Bay immediately.
No. Do not come
any closer.
I cannot control what
is happening to me.
( yells )
( tricorder beeping )
( steady tone )
His neck is broken.
No life signs.
Sick Bay, form a
resuscitation team.
I have a code seven
in Shuttle Bay Two.
Transporter room, stand by.
Hold it!
No, don't.
( inhales sharply )
Hold still.
LA FORGE:
Doc?
I can't
believe it.
There's no trace of injury.
You admit you were trying
to steal a shuttlecraft.
JOHN:
Yes.
So, I ask you again, why?
I don't know.
Unacceptable.
You had a reason.
I want to know
what it was.
Damn it, you nearly killed
a member of my crew.
And healed him.
I'm not forgetting that.
That's the reason he's
here and not in the Brig.
I warned him.
Told him it was dangerous.
Why?
Why was it dangerous?
What is happening
to you?
I don't know.
The rate of metamorphosis
is accelerating.
It's almost as if
your body is generating
an electrical field that's
warping the tissue.
Who are you?
What are you?
I'm afraid...
for myself, for all of you.
I have to get away.
Isolate myself.
Whatever is happening to me,
it's dangerous.
As Lieutenant Worf discovered.
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Captain, for the sake
of your crew,
let me go
before this happens again.
John, I don't believe you're
capable of harming any--
DATA: Captain.
The alien vessel is coming
within weapon's range.
Its shields are up.
I'm on my way.
I want him kept under
constant surveillance.
John.
I really want
to thank you.
For what?
I don't know how,
or even why,
but down on the planet,
you gave me something--
a... well,
a new confidence.
I doubt I can take
credit for that.
Perhaps I only helped you
find something you already had.
DATA:
Captain, on screen.
Alien vessel approaching
at half-impulse, sir.
Heading 051, mark 114.
Raise shields.
Slow to one-third
impulse power.
Bring us to 103, mark 025.
Mr. Worf,
hail the alien vessel.
They continue
to ignore our hail, sir.
DATA:
They are scanning us, sir.
They are answering our hail,
Captain.
On screen.
JOHN:
Sunad.
You know him?
Yes.
I don't know how,
but... he's dangerous.
I am Commander
Sunad of Zalkon.
You are trespassing
into our space
and you are holding
a Zalkonian citizen.
I'm Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the United Federation
of Planets.
We do not intend
transgression of--
You will return him
to us immediately.
Sunad, this individual
is a guest aboard our ship.
We found him dying
in a shipwreck.
We have returned him to health.
Then you aided a criminal.
He is one of four
escaped prisoners.
We eliminated
the other three.
We thought this one
dead as well.
Return him
so we may complete our task.
Of what is he accused?
He is a disruptive
influence.
He spreads lies.
He encourages dissent.
He disturbs the natural order
of our society.
In what way?
That is not your concern!
I will give you
two hours to comply.
RIKER:
Tactical analysis.
The Zalkonian ship
has a formidable armament.
Their weaponry
is comparable to ours.
They're as fast
as the Enterprise
and probably just
as maneuverable.
Counselor, do they mean
to carry out their threat?
I believe so.
Sunad's hatred
for John was evident,
but there's
something else.
The Zalkonians
are afraid of John.
Commander Riker,
Counselor, Doctor.
John, I want you
to join us.
Mr. Data, you have the Bridge.
Mr. Worf, stay at Tactical.
Counter any moves
the Zalkonian makes.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
I can neither
confirm nor deny
what the Zalkonians
told you.
They make serious
accusations against you.
Their accusations
may be true.
I don't know.
I don't believe
that I am a criminal.
You understand the
difficult position
in which I am placed.
Completely.
And I refuse to place
your ship in danger.
If necessary, I will
surrender to them.
But I am convinced
there is more at stake
here than my life.
There's something...
important I must complete.
My survival is vital.
( sighs )
If I could explain it, I would.
I'll inform you of
my decision shortly.
Captain, you can't
seriously be considering--
We must consider all options,
Doctor, and not let
our personal feelings
impede our judgment.
You're going to
tell me it's irrelevant
that we'll be sending
him to his death?
Whether we approve of the
Zalkonians' intentions
is not the issue.
But for what it's worth,
I believe that John is correct,
that his existence
has broader ramifications
than that of a simple criminal.
TROI:
Sunad thinks so.
He feels personally
threatened by John.
Sunad called John a
"disruptive influence."
That's hardly a capital offense.
It's not up to us
to judge their laws, Doctor.
RIKER: I know how I would
feel if the situation
were reversed-- if they
were in our territory
holding a Federation citizen.
The Zalkonians truly
don't understand
our indecision
about returning John.
In their eyes, we shouldn't
even be involved.
But we are involved.
I saved his life.
For what? So that they
could chase him down
and take away that life again?
Picard, we will not tolerate
more delays.
Commander,
let me remind you,
we are on a mission
of exploration.
Our purpose is to establish
peaceful relations
with the civilizations
we encounter.
We do not want
relations with you.
If that is your wish,
we will respect it.
We simply want you
to leave Zalkonian space
as soon as you return
the criminal.
Commander, we will leave.
It is not our policy
to intervene
in the affairs
of other cultures.
But before I return
the survivor to you,
I would appreciate a more
detailed explanation
of what he has done
to merit a death sentence.
As I said,
it is not your concern.
Agreed. However,
there are circumstances
of which you may be unaware.
The survivor has
suffered a memory loss.
He's therefore ill-equipped
to defend himself
against your accusations.
There is no defense.
Our judgment is final.
There's something else.
Since his recovery, he's
manifested unusual abilities.
What kind of abilities?
He apparently has the power
to heal injuries
with a simple touch.
Lies.
And even to reverse
death itself.
Obviously,
he has corrupted you as well.
I see I'm wasting my time.
( gasping )
( all gasping )
I can't breathe.
( breathing deeply )
It's come back to me, Beverly.
I know who I am...
what I am.
Ready all weapons.
You will no longer harm
these people, Sunad.
Fire upon that ship.
Do not be afraid.
I won't hurt you.
Kill him, Captain.
He's evil.
You could learn
from these people, Sunad.
They do not fear me.
They don't know how
dangerous you are--
you and the others
like you.
That is what you and
the other leaders
have maintained
for generations,
but it is not true.
Captain,
my species
is on the verge
of a wondrous
evolutionary change--
a transmutation beyond
our physical being.
I am the first of my kind
to approach this metamorphosis.
They tried to
convince us it was a sickness
we would never survive,
that the pain
and energy pulses
would kill us.
They claimed we were dangerous,
so they destroyed anyone
who exhibited the signs
of the transfiguration.
We were protecting our society.
By murdering us?
You saw the mutations
as a threat to your authority.
You were terrified of something
you couldn't understand.
Some suspected that what
was happening to them
was not evil.
Four of us decided
to flee Zalkon
and let the metamorphosis
take its course.
You hunted us down,
killed the others,
but I survived...
with the help
of a kind...
and generous people.
( voice resonating ):
There is nothing to fear.
You can join me.
All Zalkonians can.
Let me show you.
Don't touch me!
As you wish.
But others will listen,
now that you can no longer
prevent me
from telling
them the truth.
Those who are willing
will follow me.
Sunad is back aboard
the Zalkonian vessel, Captain.
My people are about to
embark on a new realm--
a new plane of existence,
thanks to you.
It is our mission
to seek out life in all forms.
We are privileged
to have been present
at the emergence
of a new species.
Beverly,
you gave me life,
and more.
I do not have the words
for my gratitude...
nor my sorrow at leaving you.