Captain's Log,
Stardate 43989.1.
The Enterprise has arrived
at Jouret IV
in response
to a distress signal
from one of the Federation's
outermost colonies.
Anything from the surface?
No, sir. There have
been no communications
from the colony
for over 12 hours.
Sensors picking up
any signs of life?
None.
The surface environment
is safe for transport,
Commander.
Mr. O'Brien.
Verify these are
accurate coordinates
for the New Providence colony.
Coordinates verified, sir.
You're at the center of town.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43992.6.
Admiral Hanson and Lieutenant
Commander Shelby
of Starfleet Tactical
have arrived to review
the disappearance
of New Providence colony.
No sign remains
of the 900 inhabitants.
The truth is...
hell, we are not ready.
We've known they were coming
for over a year.
We've thrown every resource we
have into this, but still...
RIKER:
Then you're
convinced
it is the Borg.
That's what I'm here
to find out.
The initial descriptions
of the surface conditions
are almost identical
to your report from System J-25.
Commander Riker
wrote those reports.
He agrees with you.
Commander Shelby
took over Borg tactical analysis
six months ago.
I've learned to give her
a wide latitude
when I want
to get things done.
That's how I intend
to operate here.
My priority has been
to develop some kind--
any kind--
of defense strategy.
Obviously, nothing we have now
can stop them.
We've been designing new weapons
but they're all
still on the drawing board.
We expected much more lead time.
Your encounter with the Borg
was over 7,000
light years away.
If this is the Borg
it would indicate they have
a source of power
far superior to our own.
I'd like to see the colony site
as soon as possible, Captain.
It'll be dark there
in 30 minutes.
We've scheduled an away team
for dawn.
Number One,
why don't you
show the Commander
to her quarters.
It's our poker night,
Admiral.
There's always
an open seat for you.
Another time, Commander.
Your Captain and I
have a lot to cover.
But, uh, rumor has it
Commander Shelby has
played a hand or two.
Keep your eye on her, Jean-Luc.
She's one very impressive
young lady.
You seem rather taken
with her, J.P.
Just an old man's fantasies.
When Shelby came into Tactical,
every admiral's uncle
had a take
on this Borg business.
She cut through it.
She put us on track.
Earl Grey?
Please.
She'd make you one hell
of a First Officer.
Already have a hell
Don't tell me he's going
to pass up another commission.
One's available?
The Melbourne.
It's his if he wants it.
Hasn't he told you?
He'll make a fine captain, J.P.
You may want to tell him that.
We're still waiting
on his decision.
This is the third time
we've pulled out
the Captain's chair for Riker.
He just won't sit down.
Well, let me tell you something,
Jean-Luc--
there are a lot
of young hotshots like Shelby
on the way up.
Riker could suddenly look
like he's standing still
next to them.
He's hurting his career
by staying put.
And if I were you,
I'd kick him in the rear end
for his own good.
I don't know exactly
what I'm looking for
but we've tested
the sections of the
Enterprise's hull
that were damaged
by the Borg.
There were some unusual
magnetic-resonance traces.
A Borg footprint?
That's my theory.
I'll see if it holds up
tomorrow.
I've reviewed your personnel.
I'll be assigning Mr. La Forge
and Mr. Data
to accompany me
on the away team.
I've already assigned them
to the away team.
And I'll be with you as well,
Commander.
Of course.
I appreciate any assistance
you can offer.
Tell me, Commander.
Is serving aboard the Enterprise
as extraordinary an experience
as I've heard?
Every bit.
Good, because I intend
to convince Captain Picard
that I'm the right choice
for the job.
Job? Which job?
Yours, of course.
I'm sorry.
I heard that you were leaving.
If I were, I'm sure
you'd be the first to know.
Poker's at 1700 hours
in my quarters, deck eight.
Got another king
in the hole, eh, Data?
I am afraid I cannot
answer that, Wesley
and as you are a
newcomer to the game
may I say, it is
inappropriate
for you to ask.
( players chuckle )
I will buy
another card, Counselor.
No help there.
Fold. Again.
Three jacks looking back
for the handsome young ensign.
Pair of deuces stands.
Flush, possible
straight flush.
Hmm.
Your bet, Mr. Crusher.
I'm in for ten.
Call.
Now it's time
for the long pants.
There's your ten. 100.
He's got the straight
flush, folks.
Not necessarily.
Commander Riker
may be bluffing, Wesley.
I don't think so.
Fold.
With three jacks?
What, are you kidding?
Wesley, you may get
straight A's in school
but there's a lot you
need to learn about poker.
Well, I've only got two pair
but I've got to see
your hole card.
I'll call.
( Geordi chuckles )
You got him.
Mr. Data and our guest
appear to be tardy.
Sir, Commander Shelby
and Data beamed down
to the planet's
surface an hour ago.
On whose authority?
On hers, sir.
Morning.
Early bird gets
the worm, eh?
We've had some
interesting results.
Commander Shelby...
Walk with me, Commander.
Early bird?
I believe
Commander Shelby erred.
There is no evidence
of avifaunal
or crawling vermicular
life-forms on Jouret IV.
That's not what
she meant, Data
but you're right--
she erred.
I'm sorry,
but I woke up early
and I saw that a weather
system was moving in.
It could have affected
the soil readings.
So without any regard
for the risk of coming
down here alone...
Really, Commander,
if we ran into the Borg here
two extra bodies wouldn't have
made a hell of a difference
now, would they?
We had three hours
before the storm front hit
less than two hours now.
Data was available.
I took him.
We came.
I don't see your problem.
My problem, Commander, is
I expect to be notified
before there's a
change in my orders.
Noted for future reference.
Do you wish to hear
my report, sir?
Go ahead.
The soil contains the same
magnetic-resonance traces.
That's our footprint.
There's no doubt anymore.
It is the Borg.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43993.5.
With confirmation of the Borg's
presence in Federation space
Admiral Hanson has returned
to Starbase 324
to discuss strategy
with Starfleet Command.
Lieutenant Commander Shelby
remains onboard
to continue
tactical preparations.
I've also ordered
a standing Yellow Alert.
All Federation-allied outposts
have been warned.
Ops will continue to monitor
long-range sensors.
I've assigned Data,
La Forge and Mr. Crusher
to work
with Commander Shelby.
Good.
You've covered all the bases.
What's your impression
of Shelby?
She knows her stuff.
She has your
full confidence?
Well, I think she
needs supervision.
She takes the initiative
a little too easily--
sometimes with risks.
( tsking )
Sounds like a young
Lieutenant Commander
I recruited
as a First Officer.
Perhaps.
Will...
what the hell are you
still doing here?
Sir?
You've been offered
the Melbourne.
I've decided not to pursue
that commission at this time.
She's a fine ship, Will.
Yes, but she's not the
Enterprise.
With all due respect, sir,
you need me, particularly now.
Indeed. Starfleet needs
good Captains, particularly now.
Reconsider your decision.
Are you telling me to leave,
Captain?
I'm asking you to look
at your career objectively.
Will, you're ready
to work without a net.
You're ready
to take command
and, you know, Enterprise
will go along
just fine without you.
What am I still doing here?
Deanna, I pushed myself
hard to get this far.
I... I sacrificed a lot.
I always said I wanted
my own command
and yet... something's
holding me back.
Is it wrong for me
to want to stay?
What do you think?
( sighs )
Maybe I'm just afraid
of the big chair.
I don't think so.
The Captain says
Shelby reminds him
of the way that I used to be
and he's right.
She comes in here
full of drive and ambition.
Impatient, taking risks.
I look at her and I wonder what
happened to those things in me.
I liked those things about me.
I've lost something.
You mean, you're older,
more experienced
a little more... seasoned.
"Seasoned."
That's a horrible
thing to say to a man.
I don't think
you've lost a thing.
And I think you've gained
more than you realize.
You're much more
comfortable with yourself
than you used to be.
Maybe that's the problem--
I'm too comfortable here.
I'm not sure
I know what that means.
You're happy here
happier than I've
ever known you to be.
So... it comes down
to a simple question.
What do you want, Will Riker?
SHELBY:
...a manipulation effect in the
Borg ship's subspace field.
A definite pattern
at 4.8 minute intervals
during your first
confrontation with them.
It might indicate
high-output auxiliary
generators kicking in.
One theory is that their
systems are decentralized
with redundant power sources
located throughout the ship.
That is a reasonable conclusion.
Borg technology has given
each member of their society
the ability to interface
and function
collectively.
It is likely they
have constructed their ship
with the same philosophy.
You knock out one generator
and another one takes over
without interruption.
What kind of damage would we
have to do to shut them down?
Projections suggest
that a Borg ship like this one
could continue
to function effectively
even if 78% of it
was inoperable.
And our best shot
barely scratched
the surface.
Well, from what I've seen
I can't believe that any
of these new weapon systems
can be ready in less
than 18 months, Commander.
We've been projecting 24.
Is there anything we can do here
to adapt
our current defense systems?
We'll have to go through
the specs again, but...
I don't know.
My mind's turned to clay.
Mine, too.
I think we should look
at modifying
the plasma phaser design.
Commander, I think
we should call it a night.
That's an order.
We'll reconvene at 0500.
Sir, if I may be allowed
to continue with Mr. Data
who does not require rest.
You need rest, Commander.
If we have a confrontation
with the Borg
without improving
our defense systems...
If we have a confrontation
I don't want a crew
fighting the Borg
at the same time they're
fighting their own fatigue.
Dismissed.
At 1900 hours yesterday
the USS Lalo
departed Zeta Alpha II
on a freight run
to Sentinel Minor IV.
At 2200 hours and 12 minutes
a distress signal was received
at Starbase 157.
The Lalo reported contact
with an alien vessel
described as cube-shaped.
The distress signal
ended abruptly
and she has not been
heard from since.
Mr. Data, how long would it take
to get there at warp nine?
One hour,
17 minutes, sir.
Make it so.
We're coming
with every available starship
to assist, Captain
but the closest help
is six days away.
We'll try and keep them
occupied until you arrive.
I know you will.
Hanson out.
All hands stand
to battle stations.
Commander Shelby
what is the status
of our defense preparations?
Mr. La Forge has a plan
to modulate shield nutation.
Hopefully, that'll
hold them off
for a while.
LA FORGE:
At the same
time, we'll be
retuning phasers to higher
EM base emitting frequencies
try to disrupt
their subspace field.
What's your assessment
of our potential effectiveness?
( sighs ):
It's a shot in the dark, Captain
but, for now,
it's the best we can do.
Dismissed.
( console beeping )
Sir, reading
unidentified vessel
just entering
sensor range
bearing 210
mark 151.
Hail them, Mr. Worf.
No response, sir.
Move to intercept.
WESLEY:
Aye, sir.
Sir, the vessel
has already changed course
to intercept us.
Approaching
at warp 9.3.
Entering visual range.
On screen.
Magnify.
Mr. Worf, dispatch
a subspace message
to Admiral Hanson.
We have engaged the Borg.
WORF:
Captain, you
are being hailed.
( alarm blaring )
I am?
Yes, Captain--
by name.
Data, is it the same ship
we faced at J-25?
Uncertain,
Commander.
But the dimensions
are precisely the same.
On screen.
I am Captain Jean-Luc...
BORG VOICES:
...Jean-Luc Picard, Captain
of the Starship Enterprise
registry NCC-1701-D.
You will lower your shields
and prepare
to transport yourself
aboard our vessel.
If you do not cooperate,
we will destroy your ship.
You have committed acts
of aggression
against the United Federation
of Planets.
If you do not withdraw
immediately...
You will surrender yourself
or we will destroy your ship.
Your defensive capabilities
are unable to withstand...
What the hell
do they want with you?
I thought they weren't
interested in human life-forms--
only our technology.
Their priorities seem
to have changed.
Open.
WORF:
Channel open.
We have developed new
defense capabilities
since our last meeting,
and we are prepared to use them
if you do not withdraw
from Federation space.
LA FORGE:
Captain
shields are being probed.
I'm modulating nutation.
Captain, the Borg are
attempting to lock onto us
with their tractor beam.
Load torpedo bays.
Arm phasers.
Lock coordinates on the source
of the tractor beam.
Shield status.
Holding, sir.
The nutation modulation
has them confused.
They have the ability
to analyze and adapt, Commander.
Shield modulation has failed.
They've locked on.
Shields are being drained.
90%... 80...
Trying to recalibrate nutation.
Damn!
Shields
have failed.
Fire all weapons.
Their subspace field is intact.
New phaser frequencies
had no impact.
Reverse engines.
LA FORGE:
Full reverse.
We're not moving.
Fire at will.
Launching
torpedoes.
Phaser spread
continuing.
Still no damage to
the Borg vessel, sir.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Outer hull breach.
They are cutting
into the hull--
Engineering
section.
Geordi, evacuate
Engineering.
Computer, evacuation sequence.
Sealing doors to core chamber.
Come on now.
Let's move it, people!
Let's move it. Let's go!
COMPUTER:
Warning. Inner hull failing.
Decompression danger
deck 36, section four.
Sealing Main Engineering.
Data, fluctuate phaser
resonance frequencies.
Random settings,
keep them changing.
Don't give them time
to adapt.
The tractor beam
has been released.
Warp nine.
Course 151 mark 330.
Engage.
They are in pursuit,
Captain.
Maintain course.
Damage report, Geordi.
Hull rupture
in Main Engineering.
The damage is pretty
heavy. We lost a lot of
good people down there.
11 dead, eight more
unaccounted for, Captain.
Repair teams to Engineering.
Seal hull breach.
They didn't get to the core.
I can control functions
from here.
Now approaching
the Paulson Nebula, sir.
Drop to impulse.
Take us in, Ensign.
The field's getting
too dense, sir.
Steady.
Analysis of the nebula cloud,
Mr. Data.
82% dilithium
hydroxyls...
magnesium, chromium.
Should provide
an effective screen
against their
sensors, Captain.
Mr. La Forge,
prepare to reverse engines.
Full stop.
( console beeps )
The Borg ship
is continuing scans
attempting to locate us.
Good.
As long as they're
looking for us
they won't hurt anyone else.
Time index: 514.
Data started to fluctuate
phaser resonance frequencies.
The Borg's beam breaks contact.
Slow playback.
Take a closer look,
Commander. Mr. La Forge?
LA FORGE:
There's a two percent drop
in power for an instant
but it is system-wide.
The phaser frequency spread
was in a high narrow band.
Conceivably, the ship's
power distribution nodes
are vulnerable
to those frequencies.
If we can generate
a concentrated burst of power
at that same
frequency distribution--
I mean a lot more than anything
our phasers
or photon torpedoes
could ever provide...
How do we do that?
The main deflector dish.
It's the only component
on the Enterprise
designed to channel
that much power at
controlled frequencies.
End program.
Unfortunately, there
is one slight detail.
In the process, the blast
completely destroys the
Enterprise as well.
If we could get further away,
increase the deflector's range.
SHELBY:
It could work.
In the meantime, we should
retune all phasers
including the hand units,
to the same frequency.
Proceed.
I'll inform the Captain.
There is one other
recommendation
I'd like to make, Commander.
Separate the saucer section.
Assign a skeleton crew
to create a diversion.
We may need the power from
the saucer's impulse engines.
But it would give them more
than one target to worry about.
It's too great a risk.
I'd like the Captain
to make that decision, sir.
Commander,
I bring all the alternatives
to the Captain's attention.
That will be all.
I going to need to
install higher capacity
power transfers
to the deflector
dish, Commander.
How long?
Better part
of a day.
She gets a full head
of steam, doesn't she?
Mm-hmm. She's a formidable
presence, to say the least
but I'm convinced she can
help us here, Commander.
I am, too.
Don't worry about it.
I can handle Shelby.
( door chimes )
Come.
Come in, Number One.
Commander Shelby
was just telling me
of your... concerns
about her plan.
I'm sorry if she
troubled you, sir.
I have already
informed her...
PICARD:
Yes, I entirely agree
with you, Number One.
It's not the time.
But the time may come
when we will be required
to take greater risks.
I want you to consider her plan
as a fall-back position.
Make the necessary preparations.
Very good, sir.
Deck eight,
Battle Bridge.
Halt.
Commander, you and I need
to have a conversation.
You never ordered me not to
discuss this with the Captain.
You disagree with me--
fine.
You need to take it
to the Captain-- fine.
Through me.
You do an end run
around me again
I'll snap you back so hard
you'll think you're
a first-year cadet again.
May I speak frankly, sir?
By all means.
You're in my way.
Really.
How terrible for you.
All you know how to do
is play it safe.
I suppose that's why
someone like you
sits in the shadow
of a great man
for as long as you have
passing up one command
after another.
Proceed to deck eight.
When it comes to this
ship and this crew
you're damned right
I play it safe.
If you can't make
the big decisions, Commander
I suggest you make room
for someone who can.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 43996.2.
The Enterprise remains
concealed in the dust cloud.
And, to my surprise, the Borg
have maintained their position
waiting for us
to come out of hiding.
I have no explanation
for their special interest
in me or this ship.
We continue to prepare
our defenses
for the inevitable
confrontation
but, I must admit,
on this night
I contemplate
the distinct possibility
that no defense may be adequate
against this enemy.
Captain.
Trouble sleeping?
It's something of a tradition,
Guinan--
Captain touring the ship
before a battle.
Oh.
Before a hopeless battle
if I remember
the tradition correctly.
Not necessarily.
Nelson toured the HMS Victory
before Trafalgar.
Yes, but Nelson never returned
from Trafalgar, did he?
No, but the battle
was won.
Do you expect this
battle to be won?
We may yet prevail.
That's... a conceit.
But... it's a healthy one.
I wonder if
the Emperor Honorius
watching the Visigoths
coming over the seventh hill
truly realized that the Roman
Empire was about to fall.
This is just another page
in history, isn't it?
Will this be the end
of our civilization?
Turn the page.
This isn't the end.
You say that
with remarkable assuredness.
With experience.
When the Borg destroyed
my world
my people were scattered
throughout the universe.
We survived.
As will humanity survive.
As long as there's
a handful of you
to keep
the spirit alive
you will prevail.
Even if it takes a millennium.
( explosion )
WORF:
Captain Picard,
report to the Bridge.
I'm on my way, Lieutenant.
They're some sort
of magnetometric-guided charges.
Status of shields?
WORF:
Back to 48%, Captain.
Mr. La Forge, I may have
to take us out of the nebula.
I want all the power
you can give me.
Engines are ready, Captain.
Recommend you adjust
shield harmonics
to favor the upper EM band
when you proceed.
Acknowledged.
Direct hit, deck nine.
Damage report.
Structural latching system
integrity breached.
Prepare to take us
out of here, Number One.
Fire up the engines.
Half impulse till we
clear the nebula
then punch it up
to warp nine.
Ready phasers, load
forward torpedo bays.
Engage.
Borg tractor beam
is attempting to lock on.
Fire at will.
Continue rotating
shield frequency.
( console beeping )
Shields failing.
( insistent beeping )
Tractor beam has locked on.
It's no use.
They've already adapted
to the new frequencies.
( grunts )
The Borg ship
is disengaging.
Leaving at
warp speed.
Maintain pursuit.
Borg vessel has reached
warp nine, 9.4, 9.6.
Stay with them.
Riker to O'Brien.
Can you get a fix
on the Captain?
Negative, sir.
There's some kind
of interference.
I can't lock in on his signal.
Senior officers,
report to the Bridge.
Sir, the coordinates
they have set--
they are on a
direct course
to Sector 001--
the Terran system.
Earth.
BORG VOICES:
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
you lead the strongest ship
of the Federation fleet.
You speak for your people.
I have nothing to say to you
and I will resist you
with my last ounce of strength.
Strength is irrelevant.
Resistance is futile.
We wish to improve ourselves.
We will add your biological
and technological
distinctiveness to our own.
Your culture will adapt
to service ours.
Impossible.
My culture is based on freedom
and self-determination.
Freedom is irrelevant.
Self-determination
is irrelevant.
You must comply.
We would rather die.
Death is irrelevant.
Your archaic cultures
are authority driven.
To facilitate our introduction
into your societies
it has been decided that a human
voice will speak for us
in all communications.
You have been chosen
to be that voice.
WORF:
Commander, they
are leading us
into the heart
of our own defenses.
Yeah, well, so far,
they haven't had
much of a reason
to worry about our defenses.
Commander, if the Borg
stay at warp 9.6
we'll be forced
to discontinue pursuit
and power down
in less than three hours.
Two hours,
40 minutes,
three seconds.
How long before
the deflector's ready?
We're close, a few hours maybe.
I know-- I'll get it done
in two somehow
but, Commander, I'm going
to need serious power
from the warp engines
to make this weapon work.
So far, we're using
everything we've got
just to keep up with them.
Sir, we've got to get that ship
down to impulse.
I'm leading an away team over
there to get the Captain back.
We'll find a way
to get them out of warp.
Ensign Crusher, you continue
to assist Mr. La Forge.
Commander Shelby,
you'll take the Bridge
and coordinate
with Starfleet.
Data, Worf, Doctor,
you're with me.
Excuse me, sir.
With my knowledge
of the Borg...
Those are my
orders, Commander!
TROI:
Commander Riker
it is inappropriate for you
to lead the away team.
Until the return
of Captain Picard
you are in command
of the Enterprise.
We're in
a state of war
and your place
is on the Bridge.
Commander Shelby
you'll lead
the away team.
Make it so.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 43998.5.
Our pursuit of the Borg
continues on a course
that will take us
to the very core
of the Federation.
The devastation they could
bring is beyond imagination.
These phasers
have been retuned.
Each has a different frequency
spanning the upper EM band.
All right, a reminder--
we only get to use
each of these once,
maybe twice
before the Borg
learn to adapt.
Don't fire
until you have to.
What kind of resistance
should we expect?
At our first encounter,
the Borg virtually ignored us
when we beamed aboard
their vessel.
Clearly, they did not consider
our being there a threat.
That may change, however
if we start interfering
with their plans.
Shelby to Bridge.
Away team ready.
We've got 58 minutes
before we have to power down
and disengage.
Understood.
Proceed. Commander?
No unnecessary risks.
Clear?
Very clear, sir.
Shelby out.
We've matched warp velocity
for transport, Commander.
Energize.
WORF:
Tricorder functions minimal.
Any signs of human life?
Inconclusive.
Look at this.
This is extraordinary.
Those appear to be
some kind of power
waveguide conduits
which allow them
to work collectively
as they perform
ship functions.
There's no way to take
out enough of these
to disable them.
What if we
look at this
from the mosquito's
point of view?
Interesting metaphor, Doctor.
What is your idea?
If we sting them
in a tender spot
they might stop for
a minute to scratch.
Distribution
nodes.
SHELBY:
If we take out a few of these,
it just might make them scratch.
The Captain's
communicator--
it is still activated.
Crusher to Picard.
Can you hear me?
Can you locate it, Worf?
This way.
I strongly recommend redeploying
all available defenses
to protect Sector 001, Admiral.
We're moving to intercept
at Wolf 359.
We'll make our stand there.
How much longer can you
maintain pursuit?
22 minutes if they stay
at their current speed.
If we can't bring them
out of warp
we'll do as much damage
as we can
before we have to disengage.
Picard?
Nothing yet, sir.
( tricorder beeping )
( beeping faster )
In here.
Shelby to Enterprise.
Go ahead.
We've found
the Captain's uniform
and his communicator.
We're resuming our search.
Stand by, Commander.
We're in business.
It'll burn out
the main deflector
but it'll be one
hell of a bang.
Radiation danger?
We're going to have
to evacuate
the entire forward half
of the secondary hull
and the lower three
decks of the saucer.
I'll see to that.
Commander Shelby
we have only 17 minutes
of warp power left.
Do whatever you can
to get them out of warp.
Acknowledged.
Shelby out.
Let's take out some
of these distribution nodes
and see what happens.
Sir, they've done it.
The Borg ship
is dropping out of warp.
Go to impulse.
Aye, sir.
Diverting warp power
to main deflector.
Move us to within
40,000 kilometers
and match velocity.
Commence arming sequence.
Increase deflector modulation
to upper frequency band.
Shelby to Enterprise.
Encountering resistance.
Prepare to beam us
back on my signal.
SHELBY:
They're adapting
to the frequencies.
Jean-Luc.
Captain!
( gasps )
( grunts )
Enterprise, get us out of here.
The Captain?
We were unable to
retrieve him, sir.
The Captain has been
altered by the Borg.
Altered?
He is a Borg.
We'll go back.
I need more people.
We need to retune
the phasers again.
We'll get him
out of there.
LA FORGE:
Commander.
Reading subspace field
fluctuations from within
the Borg ship.
Looks like
they're...
regenerating-- restoring power.
They could be capable
of warp any minute.
Is the deflector ready?
It's ready.
Will, he's alive.
If we could get him
back to the ship
I might be able
to restore...
This is our only chance
to destroy them.
If they get back into warp,
our weapon is useless.
We'll sabotage them again
if we have to.
We can't maintain power.
We don't have the time.
Prepare to fire.
At least consult
with Starfleet Command.
Get Admiral Hanson
on subspace.
Belay that order, Lieutenant.
There's no time.
Sir, we are being hailed
by the Borg.
On screen.
I am Locutus of Borg.
Resistance is futile.
Your life, as it has been,
is over.
From this time forward,
you will service us.
Mr. Worf... fire.