Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
Mr. Worf,
dispatch a subspace message
to Admiral Hanson.
We have engaged the Borg.
Data, fluctuate phaser
resonance frequencies.
Random settings,
keep them changing.
Don't give them
time to adapt.
We're coming with
every available starship
to assist, Captain
but the closest help
is six days away.
All you know how to do
is play it safe.
If you can't make
the big decisions, Commander
I suggest you make room
for someone who can.
( grunts )
If we can generate
a concentrated burst of power
at that same
frequency
distribution...
How do we do that?
The main deflector dish.
Shelby to Enterprise.
We've found
the Captain's uniform
and his communicator.
Jean-Luc.
We were unable to
retrieve him, sir.
The Captain has been
altered by the Borg.
CRUSHER:
Will, he's alive.
If we could get him back
to the ship, I might be
able to restore...
This is our only chance
to destroy them.
If they get back into warp,
our weapon is useless.
I am Locutus of Borg.
From this time forward,
you will service us.
Mr. Worf... fire.
And now, the conclusion.
LA FORGE:
Deflector power
approaching maximum limits.
Energy discharge in six seconds.
WORF:
Firing, sir.
The Borg ship is undamaged.
Impossible.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Warp reactor core
primary coolant failure.
I can't maintain it much longer,
Commander.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Exceeding
reaction chamber thermal limit.
Cease fire.
Shutting down warp engines.
They couldn't have
adapted that quickly.
The knowledge and experience
of the human, Picard
is part of us now.
It has prepared us for all
possible courses of action.
Your resistance is hopeless...
Number One.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 44001.4.
The Borg ship has resumed
its course toward Earth.
We are unable to pursue pending
repairs to the Enterprise.
As we anticipated,
the blast burned out
our main navigational deflector.
We also have damage
to our shields
and our reactor core.
We should be back up
in eight to 12 hours, Admiral.
Well, we'll miss you
at the party.
The Enterprise will be there.
Maybe a little late,
but we'll be there, sir.
Your engagements have
given us valuable time.
We've mobilized a fleet
of 40 starships at Wolf 359.
And that's just for starters.
The Klingons are sending
warships.
Hell, we've even thought
of opening communications
with the Romulans.
You realize, Admiral, that with
the assistance of Captain Picard
the Borg will be ready
for your defenses.
Lieutenant, a few years ago,
I watched a freshman cadet
pass four upperclassmen
on the last hill
of a 40-kilometer run
at Danula II.
The damnedest thing I ever saw.
The only freshman to ever win
the Academy marathon.
I made it my business
to get to know that young fellow
and I got to know him
very, very well.
And I'll tell you something--
I never met anyone
with more drive, determination
or more courage
than Jean-Luc Picard
and there is no way in hell
that he would assist the Borg.
I want that clear.
Of course, Admiral.
He is... a casualty of war.
CRUSHER:
Then we have
abandoned
all hope of recovering him.
In less than 24 hours
this armada's going to hit
that Borg vessel
with everything we can muster.
Either they survive or we do.
And as for Picard...
a great man has been lost.
Your Captain.
My friend.
Commander Riker,
I hereby promote you
to the field commission
of Captain.
The Enterprise is your ship now.
Congratulations.
I wish the circumstances
were different.
Likewise.
Good luck, Admiral.
Mm. To us all.
( whirring and clicking )
And Mr. Crusher suggests
we might design a chip
that would automatically
re-tune the phasers
to a random setting
after each discharge.
Engineering.
That would be
a great advantage.
We should also see
if there's some way
that we can neutralize
their force fields.
We've got to let
them know that we can
adapt, too, Mr. Worf.
We're no longer just
fighting the Borg.
We're fighting
the life experience
they've stolen
from Captain Picard.
Now, how the hell do
we defeat an enemy
that knows us better
than we know ourselves?
The Borg have neither
honor nor courage.
That is our greatest
advantage.
I hope it's enough.
Accelerator coils
are responding normally.
Excellent.
Forward shields at 58%.
Aft shields...
Sensors must be down.
Checking. Sensors are fine.
No, aft shields
have completely failed.
Damn it! Auxiliary
generators are out again.
Just the man I need.
We're having some problems
with the aft shields.
The generator's
going on and off-line.
I could really use
your help, Worf.
How soon do we
get underway, Geordi?
Still a couple of hours.
Commander Shelby
can fill you in.
The main navigational deflector
is functional again.
Sherbourne and Barclay
are running through
the final testing
sequence now.
The warp reactor core?
Reconstruction
is proceeding normally.
It's slow work.
If we can nail down this
shield generator problem
I agree with La Forge.
We should be back
at operating capacity
in two to three hours.
Good.
Anything else, sir?
Yes. You did a good job
on the Borg ship.
I didn't get Picard.
You stopped them.
You gave us our shot.
Sir, I...
Commander, we don't have
to like each other
to work well together.
As a matter of fact
I'd like you to continue
to keep me on my toes.
Some might define
that as the role
of a First Officer.
Damn, you are ambitious,
aren't you, Shelby?
Captain Riker, based
on our past relationship
there's no reason
for me to expect
to become your First Officer
except that you need me.
I know how
to get things done
and I have the expertise
in the Borg.
And you have a lot
to learn, Commander.
Yes, sir.
Almost as much as I had to
learn when I came onboard
as Captain Picard's
First Officer.
A fact he reminded me of
when I commented
on what a pain in
the neck you are.
Yes, sir.
Data to Riker.
Message from Starfleet, Captain.
Go ahead, Data.
Starfleet reports
it has engaged the Borg
at Wolf 359, sir.
Admiral Hanson
on subspace, Captain.
On screen.
Admiral?
The fight does not
go well, Enterprise.
We're attempting
to withdraw and regroup.
Rendezvous with fleet...
( fluctuating beeps )
RIKER:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44002.3.
Repairs are complete
and the Enterprise
is warping to rendezvous
with Starfleet at Wolf 359.
Communications from the site
of battle have been cut off
possibly due
to Borg interference.
Lieutenant Worf,
everyone in this room
shares my respect
for your service to this ship
but, right now, I need
your experience at tactical.
Commander Data, I realize
your very nature omits ambition.
Nevertheless,
I want you to know
I seriously considered you
as First Officer.
Thank you, sir.
But this is not
the time for change.
I need all of you
where you are
where Captain Picard
always relied on you.
I have been... reluctantly...
forced to conclude
that Commander Shelby,
our expert on the Borg
is an ideal choice at this time
for First Officer.
Based on our latest
communication, we can assume
that the Borg survived
the fleet's attack.
Your thoughts
on our next encounter.
What about the heavy graviton
beam we were talking about?
I've gone over it four times.
The local field distortion
just wouldn't be strong enough
to incapacitate them.
Dr. Crusher and I
have been working on
an interesting premise.
With our recent experience
in nanotechnology
we might be able to introduce
a destructive breed of nanites
into the Borg.
Nanites?
Robots
small enough to enter
living cells.
How long would it take
to execute that?
That's the problem--
two to three weeks.
In two or three weeks,
nanites may be
all that's left
of the Federation.
We have the new phaser adapters.
LA FORGE:
Maybe in concert
with the photon torpedoes,
we can slow them down.
I'm sure Captain Picard
would have something
meaningful and inspirational
to say right now.
To tell you the truth,
I wish he was here
'cause I'd like to hear it, too.
I know how difficult
this transition
has been
for all of you.
I can take over for him
but I could never replace
Captain Picard
nor would I ever try.
Whatever the outcome
I'm sure our efforts
in the coming battle
will justify his faith
in all of us.
Dismissed.
What would you do?
( door chimes )
Come.
May I speak
to you, Captain?
Actually, Guinan, I...
You know, Picard
and I used to talk
every now and then
when one of us
needed to.
I guess I'm just used
to having the Captain's ear.
What's on your mind?
I've heard a lot of people
talking down in Ten-Forward.
They expect to be dead
in the next day or so.
They trust you.
They like you.
But they don't believe
anyone can save them.
I'm not sure anyone can.
When a man is convinced
he's going to die tomorrow
he'll probably find a way
to make it happen.
The only one who can
turn this around is you.
I'll do the best I can.
You're going to have to do
something you don't want to do.
You have to let go of Picard.
Maybe you haven't heard.
I tried to kill him yesterday.
You tried to kill whatever
that is on the Borg ship--
not Picard.
( sighs )
Picard is still
here with us.
In this room.
If he had died,
it would be easier.
But he didn't.
They took him from us
a piece at a time.
Did he ever tell you
why we're so close?
No.
Oh.
Then let me just say
that our relationship
is beyond friendship,
beyond family.
And I will let him go.
And you must do the same.
There can only be
one Captain.
It's not that simple.
This was his crew.
He wrote the book on this ship.
If the Borg know
everything he knows
it's time to throw
that book away.
You must let him go, Riker.
It's the only way
to beat him.
The only way to save him.
And that is now your chair...
Captain.
WESLEY:
We are now approaching
the Wolf system, Captain.
On my way.
Slow to impulse.
Take us to the battle
coordinates, Mr. Crusher.
Yellow Alert.
WORF:
Sensors are picking up
several vessels, Captain.
The fleet?
No active
subspace fields.
Negligible
power readings.
Life signs?
Negative, sir.
Visual
contact.
On screen.
SHELBY:
The Tolstoy.
The Kyushu.
The Melbourne.
Sir, sensors are picking up
unusually strong eddy currents
bearing 200 mark 211.
Data, analysis?
It could indicate the course
of the Borg ship, sir.
Ensign Crusher, set
in a course that
follows those currents.
Commander Shelby,
prepare to initiate
your plan to separate
the saucer section
when we find the Borg.
Sir, I must remind you
that Captain Picard
was briefed on that plan.
The Borg will be
prepared for it.
I'm aware of that,
Commander.
In fact, I'm
counting on it.
Crusher, Cartaino, Gleason,
report to the Battle Bridge.
Mr. Data,
Mr. Worf
I have a special mission
for you.
RIKER:
Locutus of Borg
this is Captain William T. Riker
of the USS Enterprise.
You may speak.
We wish to end
the hostilities.
Then you must
unconditionally surrender.
We are prepared to meet
to discuss your terms.
It is unlikely you are prepared
to discuss terms.
It is more likely that this is
an attempt at deception.
Come now, Locutus.
If Picard's knowledge
and experience
is part of you
then you know that
I've never lied to him.
You should also
implicitly trust me.
Is that not so?
Picard implicitly trusted you.
Then trust me now.
Meet to discuss your terms.
Discussion is irrelevant.
There are no terms.
You will disarm all your weapons
and escort us to Sector 001
where we will begin assimilating
your culture and techno...
Mr. Gleason, can you
pinpoint the source
of the Borg transmission?
I can put you within
30 meters of it, sir.
O'Brien, report.
The Borg have adapted
their electromagnetic field
to prevent main
transporter
function, sir.
RIKER:
As expected.
Mr. Data, Mr. Worf,
proceed as we discussed.
Aye, Captain.
CREWMAN:
Channel open, sir.
We would like time
to prepare our people
for assimilation.
Preparation is irrelevant.
Your people will be assimilated
as easily as Picard has been.
Your attempt at a delay
will not be successful,
Number One.
We will proceed to Earth
and if you attempt to intervene,
we will destroy you.
Then take your best shot,
Locutus
'cause we are
about to intervene.
CREWMAN:
Channel closed.
Reset subspace
communications.
Scrambler code, Riker One.
Scrambler code
Riker One,
acknowledged.
Shelby, report.
Ready for separation.
Make it so.
Auto-sep sequence initiated.
Docking latches clear.
Separation complete.
Saucer velocity, 100 meters
per second and increasing, sir.
Open fire. All weapons.
Fire.
Borg tractor beam
attempting to lock on, sir.
Evasive maneuvers,
pattern Riker Alpha.
Riker Alpha, confirmed.
They're ignoring
the saucer section completely.
Just as you should, Captain.
Ensign, evasive pattern
Riker Beta.
Riker Beta, confirmed.
Proceed to second phase,
Commander Shelby.
Acknowledged.
Fire antimatter spread.
Shuttle launch sequence
confirmed.
Departing Enterprise
in exactly three seconds.
( explosions )
The Borg tractor beam has moved
toward the antimatter spread.
They might be picking up
the engine ionization
from the shuttle.
Data, cut your engines.
Take her in unpowered.
Shuttle has penetrated
the Borg
electromagnetic field.
RIKER:
Understood.
The shuttle
escape transporter
should provide
enough power
to beam us onto the Borg ship
from here, sir.
Proceed.
WORF:
Data!
( grunting with effort )
Mission accomplished.
We have him.
Firing shuttle
thrusters.
WESLEY:
They're clear
of the Borg field, sir.
Beam them out of there,
Mr. O'Brien.
Locked in.
Transport
successful, sir.
Captain, we've sustained damage
to the impulse drive.
The saucer section is disabled.
Reading subspace
field fluctuations
from the Borg ship.
Looks like they're getting
ready to increase power.
Stand by, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
The saucer section's
a sitting duck.
Prepare to draw their fire.
Captain, the Borg ship
is moving away.
It's resuming its course
towards Earth, sir.
Rendezvous
with the saucer section.
Lay in a course of pursuit.
There is extensive
infiltration
of the microcircuit fibers
into the surrounding tissue.
His DNA is being rewritten.
Can you revive him?
I'd like more
time to study
the structural changes
in the motor pathways.
RIKER:
We don't have
more time, Doctor.
Once he was wired into the Borg
they knew everything
that he knew.
I just hope it goes both ways.
If we're lucky, he had access
to everything we need
to know about them.
Especially their
vulnerabilities.
Jean-Luc, it's Beverly.
Can you hear me?
Beverly... Crusher... Doctor.
Yes.
Don't try to move.
I am on board the Enterprise.
That's right.
A futile maneuver.
Incorrect strategy, Number One
to risk your
crew and ship
to retrieve
only one man.
Picard would never
have approved.
You underestimate
us, if you believe
this abduction
is any concern.
There is no need
for apprehension.
I intend no harm.
No harm.
I will continue
aboard this ship,
to speak for the Borg
while they continue,
without further diversion
to Sector 001
where they will force
your unconditional surrender.
Using multimodal
reflection sorting
I have been able to detect
a complex series
of subspace signals
between Locutus
and the Borg ship.
That's how they're
controlling him?
It is not just a matter
of control, Doctor.
The signals are interactive
across a subspace domain
similar to that
of a transporter beam.
I would hypothesize
that these frequencies
form the basis of the Borg's
collective consciousness.
Can't we block them?
Possibly, but as you may recall,
on several occasions
we have witnessed
the Borg removing key circuits
from injured comrades.
No doubt separating them
from the group consciousness.
The injured Borg
immediately
self-destructed.
That is correct, sir.
Cutting the link
to Locutus might be
fatal to the Captain.
We have to find a way
to reach him.
We must know what he knows.
Without
these interactive signals
it would only be a matter
of microsurgery--
I could do it.
But as long
as these Borg implants
are functioning,
there's no way
I can separate the man
from the machine.
Then perhaps there is a way
I can access the machine,
Doctor.
Worf. Klingon species.
A warrior race.
You, too,
will be assimilated.
The Klingon Empire
will never yield.
Why do you resist?
We only wish to raise
quality of life
for all species.
I like my species
the way it is.
A narrow vision.
You will become one
with the Borg.
You will all become one
The android...
Data...
primitive artificial organism.
You will be obsolete
in the new order.
Take him to your lab, Data.
Shelby to Riker.
Go ahead.
Captain, the Borg
have entered Sector 001.
The Borg have dropped
out of warp, sir.
Jupiter Outpost 92
reported visual contact
at 1200 hours,
13 minutes.
Planetary defenses?
Responding.
No reports on effectiveness
but I really can't believe
that against the Borg...
Ensign Crusher, at
their current speed
when will they
reach Earth?
27 minutes.
The soonest we
could intercept?
( sighs ):
42 minutes, sir.
Riker to Data.
What's your status?
The initial
cybernetic connection
into Captain Picard's neural net
pathways has been established.
Mr. O'Brien is ready
to process
the Borg signal
through the transport
pattern buffer.
Make it so.
With dispatch, Mr. Data.
Proceeding immediately, sir.
Data out.
The neural link
will be established
in three stages.
Doctor, I suggest
you closely observe
Captain Picard's life signs
while, at each stage
Chief O'Brien monitors
my positronic matrix activity.
Counselor
hopefully, you will
be able to determine
whether I am reaching
Captain Picard.
At what point
should I shut it down
if there's a problem?
I do not know.
I have never done this before.
Initiating first neural link.
The Captain's vital signs
are stable.
Positronic activity unchanged.
First neural connection
is confirmed.
I cannot report
any significant access
to the Borg consciousness.
WORF:
It is confirmed.
The Borg have broken through
the Mars Defense Perimeter.
Enterprise now
approaching Terran
system, sir.
Slow to impulse.
Time to intercept?
23 minutes,
14 seconds, sir.
Second neural connection
is confirmed.
I still
cannot report
any significant access.
Proceeding
with the final link.
CRUSHER:
Significant increase
in premotor area
and hypothalamus
activity.
His heartbeat is accelerating
rapidly.
Sir, your submicron
matrix activity
is increasing
exponentially.
Neural connections complete.
I have access
to the Borg subspace signals.
Processing.
Data.
Stand by.
Processing.
Fascinating.
The Borg group
consciousness
is divided into subcommands
necessary to carry out
all functions.
Defense,
communication, navigation--
they are all controlled
by a root command
implanted into ea...
( gasps )
CRUSHER:
Data, I'm picking
up increased
neural activity
in Captain Picard
localized in the
prefrontal and
parietal lobes.
The Borg might be trying
to terminate
their link with him.
Negative.
The subspace signal
configuration is unchanged.
What is causing the increased
neural activity is unclear.
No, it's not.
It's him.
It's Picard.
Troi to Bridge.
Data has made first contact
with Captain Picard.
Can you communicate
with him, Data?
I have been unable
to create a neural path
around the Borg implants, sir.
It is Captain Picard himself
who has somehow managed
to initiate contact.
WORF:
Sir, the Borg have halted
their approach to Earth.
I think we got
their attention.
Time to intercept?
Two minutes,
four seconds, sir.
They're worried.
They're worried because
we have access to Picard.
Mr. Data, we have two minutes
to figure out
what we can do with it.
Sir, it is clear the Borg
are either unwilling
or unable to terminate
their subspace links.
That may be
their Achilles heel, Captain--
their interdependency.
What do you mean, Doctor?
He's part of their collective
consciousness now.
Cutting him off would be
like asking one of us
to disconnect an arm
or a foot-- we can't do it.
They operate as a single mind.
One of them
jumps off a cliff
they all jump off?
Data, is it possible
to plant a command
into the Borg collective
consciousness?
It is conceivable, sir
but it would require
altering the pathway
from the root command
to affect all iterative
branchpoints in...
Make every
effort, Mr. Data.
Sir, what command
shall I attempt to plant?
Something
straightforward
like "disarm your
weapons systems."
( console beeping )
Visual contact with the Borg.
On screen.
RIKER:
Magnify.
Sensors reading increased power
generation from the Borg.
Red Alert.
Load all torpedo bays.
Ready phasers.
Aye, Captain.
Status of Borg weapons.
Their weapon systems
are fully charged.
Data?
Attempting to reroute
subcommand paths, Captain.
Defense systems are protected
by access barriers.
Borg attempting to lock on
tractor beam.
Rotate shield
frequencies.
Data, report.
I am unable to penetrate
defense systems command
structure, Captain.
Try the power systems, Data.
See if you can get them
to power down.
Acknowledged.
Attempting new power
subcommand path.
Shields have failed.
They've locked on, sir.
They're pulling us in.
Fire all weapons.
I cannot penetrate Borg power
subcommand structure, sir.
All critical subcommands
are protected, Captain.
Then it's over.
Mr. Crusher, ready
a collision course
with the Borg ship.
You heard me--
a collision course!
Yes, sir.
Mr. La Forge, prepare
to go to warp power.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
Sleep.
He's regaining
consciousness.
Sleep.
It's Captain
Picard speaking
not Locutus.
Sleep, Data.
He's exhausted.
Yes, Doctor.
But if I may make
a supposition
I do not believe
his message
was intended
to express fatigue
but to suggest
a course of action.
Borg cutting beam activated.
Mr. Crusher.
Eng...
Data to Bridge.
Stand by.
Stand by
all stations.
I am attempting to penetrate
the Borg regenerative
subcommand path.
It is a low-priority system
and may be accessible.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Outer hull breach.
Sir, shall I execute
evacuation sequence?
Negative, Mr. Worf.
Mr. Data, your final report.
DATA:
Stand by.
I can't, Mr. Data!
COMPUTER:
Warning. Inner hull failure
imminent on decks 23, 24 and 25.
Decompression danger.
Mr. Data,
what the hell happened?
I successfully
planted a command
into the Borg
collective consciousness.
It misdirected them
to believe it was time
to regenerate.
In effect,
I put them all to sleep.
To sleep?
DATA:
Yes, sir.
Status of Borg power drive?
Minimal power.
Electromagnetic field?
Nonexistent.
Commander Shelby,
take an away team
and confirm that the Borg are...
asleep.
Delighted, sir.
Mr. Worf.
Shelby to Enterprise.
It's true.
They're all
in a regeneration mode.
They're dormant, sir.
Any indication to how long
we can keep them like this?
Checking.
Tricorder readings
are fluctuating
rapidly, Commander.
Shelby to Enterprise.
There are indications here
that their entire power net's
about to feed
back on itself.
I'd say we're looking at
a self-destruct sequence
activated by the
Borg's malfunction.
Do you want us to
attempt to disarm it?
Stand by.
There's no way to know
what the destruction of the Borg
ship will do to him.
DATA:
We should also
consider the
advantages
of further examination of the
Borg and their vessel, sir.
I don't think so.
Data, separate yourself
from Captain Picard.
Away team,
get yourselves home.
Mr. Crusher,
upon their return
move us
to a safe position.
Aye, sir.
Life signs are stable.
The DNA around
the microcircuit fiber implants
is returning to normal.
How do you feel?
Almost human.
With just...
a bit of a headache.
We'll get you to Sick Bay.
We won't have any trouble
getting those implants out now.
How much do you remember?
Everything.
Including some brilliantly
unorthodox strategy
from a former First Officer
of mine.
...and Earth Station
McKinley has advised
that they're ready to begin
refitting the Enterprise.
And the estimated
time for repairs?
Five or six weeks.
( door chimes )
Come.
Request permission
to disembark, sir.
Permission granted.
They picked
a fine officer
for the task force,
Commander.
We'll have
the fleet back up
in less than a year.
I imagine
you'll have your choice
of any Starfleet command, sir.
Everyone is so concerned
about my next job.
With all due respect,
Commander... sir
my career plans
are my own business
and no one else's.
But it's nice to know
I'll have
a few options.
I hope I have the fortune
of serving with you again, sir.
Captain.
Course for Station McKinley
ready and laid in, sir.
Make it so, Number One.