Captain's Log,
Stardate 44012.3.
The Enterprise remains docked
at McKinley Station
undergoing
a major overhaul and refit
following the Borg incident.
I am confident
that the ship and her crew
will soon be ready
to return to service.
Thank you.
Please take that
to Engineering.
Phaser upgrades
are complete, Commander.
Already?
And we have begun power
supply calibration.
Well, you're just too
damned efficient Lieutenant.
Thank you, sir.
Continue with the
testing, Mr. Worf.
Here's the final schedule
for the shore leave
and for the personnel
transfers.
By the way, I'm
looking forward to
meeting your parents.
Sir?
They're on the
visitors' list.
You didn't know?
No, sir.
It is inappropriate
for a Klingon
to receive
family while on duty.
As humans, my parents
do not understand.
Well, I'm not sure
that I would either, Worf
since this isn't a Klingon ship.
If you don't want
to see your parents
that's your business
but we don't get back
to Earth that often.
I'm sure we could
arrange for you to have
more off-duty time
while they're here.
No... sir.
That will not
be necessary.
Dismissed.
Mr. Worf.
If you're worried
that they might learn
about what happened
on the Klingon planet...
Not at all.
I have already informed them
by correspondence
of my discommendation.
I do not believe any human
can truly understand
my dishonor.
So, where have you
decided to go?
Hmm? What?
Oh... uh, France.
Labarre-- my
home village.
Really?
Yes.
It's the first time
in almost 20 years.
Interesting.
Counselor...
I just find it
interesting.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
the man who couldn't
be pried out of his seat
for a vacation
for three years...
It's Earth. It's home.
Do I need
another reason?
I don't know.
What do you think?
Your help has been invaluable
during my recovery
but, look... I'm, uh...
I'm better.
The injuries are healing.
Those you can see in the mirror.
The nightmares have ended.
All I need now is
a little time to myself.
I agree.
In fact, I'm delighted
you're going.
It's just that... the choice
of where you're going
could stand some scrutiny.
If you wish to believe
that my going home
is a direct result of being
held captive by the Borg
be my guest.
Is that what
you believe?
I hate it when
you do that.
Captain, you do need time.
You cannot achieve
complete recovery
so quickly.
And it's perfectly normal,
after what you've been through
to spend a great deal of time
trying to find yourself again.
And what better place
to find oneself
than on the streets
of one's home village.
Interesting.
Have a good trip,
Captain.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
They still have
not signaled?
No, sir.
My mother is never on time.
It is so... human of her.
Well, you know women.
I am not looking forward
to this.
I wish they would come
so it would begin
and end sooner.
I know what you mean,
Lieutenant.
Unlikely.
Last time my old man
was on board
I found him chasing
Nurse Stanton
around a bio-bed
in Sick Bay.
I'm not concerned about
my father chasing nurses.
Ah, but it's always something
with parents, isn't it?
WOMAN:
Enterprise, this is
Earth Station Bobruisk.
Two to transport aboard.
Energizing.
Mother, Father.
Worf.
You look good, son.
Put on a little
weight, huh?
No.
Sure you have.
Looks good on you.
Still working out with
those holodeck monsters,
I bet.
Let me take you...
Ah...
always good to meet
another chief petty officer.
Sergey Rozhenko, formerly
of the USS Intrepid.
Miles Edward O'Brien, sir.
Good to meet you.
Don't call me "sir."
I used to work
for a living.
He's joking.
The proudest
moment of his life
was when Worf earned
his commission.
Can you imagine an old
enlisted man like me
raising a boy
to be an officer?
Come along, Sergey.
There's plenty of time
to chat with the boys.
Your father has been
so looking
forward to this.
Yes, I want to
see everything--
the whole ship.
At home, I have
all the specs and diagrams
of the Galaxy-class
starships.
We are in the midst
of a repair.
I cannot give you
a complete tour.
Oh, I'm sure if you
asked the Captain...
You agreed not
to embarrass him.
Besides,
we have come
to see Worf,
not the ship.
Fine. Fine. Okay.
Your hair is a little longer,
isn't it, Worf?
( bushes rustling )
All right, whoever you are,
I can hear you.
Oh, good lord,
a highwayman.
A what?
A highwayman.
It's a robber who
attacks travelers
but none have
been reported
in this vicinity
for centuries.
But I'm not a robber.
Oh. I'm much
relieved, sir.
I know who you are.
Then you have
the advantage.
You're my nephew, Jean-Luc.
From the Starship
Enterprise.
Then you must be
my Uncle Rene.
I'm not your uncle.
It's the other way around.
Too bad, I rather
enjoyed the idea.
Why have you been
away so long?
Well, Starfleet
keeps me very busy.
Father says
you don't like it here.
I'm sure you
misunderstood.
No, I didn't.
He said so.
Well, Robert
and I, we...
Perhaps it's time
to change all that.
You know, you
don't seem so arro...
arro... you know.
Arrogant?
Yes, arrogant.
You don't seem
that way to me.
What does it mean, anyway?
Arrogant son-of-a...
Let's talk about
that later, shall we?
Mommy, he's here!
Mommy!
He's here!
Jean-Luc.
Marie.
It is so good
to finally meet you.
For me, too.
How are you feeling?
Oh, I'm fine.
Well, Robert and I
are delighted
that you've come
to stay with us.
I was...
I was thinking, I-I...
I might be imposing.
I could very easily stay
in the village.
Oh, I wouldn't hear of it.
It's your home and it
will always be your home.
Do things look that different?
PICARD:
Oh, no.
In fact, it's amazing
how little it has changed.
Everything is exactly
as I remember it.
The house, hills.
Every tree, every bush
seems untouched
by the passage of time.
Robert has worked hard
to keep it that way.
It's...
it's very important to him.
As it was to our father.
Someday I'm going to
be a Starship Captain.
You look exactly like Robert
when he was your age.
I half expect
to see myself
as a boy, come running
out of that door to play.
Robert can't wait to see you.
Rene has already
told me.
Where is he?
As usual, with his vines.
So, you arrived at last.
Welcome home, Captain.
Hello, Robert.
You, uh... shuttled in
from the village?
No, I...
I decided to walk.
I met Marie and Rene.
Good... good.
It's, um...
good to see you.
Are you tired?
No.
Well, make yourself at home.
You know where everything is.
We generally eat about 8:00.
I must try and cure
this poor, sick vine.
I'll see you shortly.
So, you'll have a chance
to visit the surface?
TROI:
Maybe.
Will and I have
been talking
about going back
to Angel Falls.
Oh, Venezuela's beautiful.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Great.
Thank you.
Something from home?
I left it here in storage
a long time ago
after Jack died.
Odds and ends, mostly.
How to Advance Your Career
Through Marriage?
It was a joke.
Jack sent it to me
when I was still
in medical school.
It was his way
of proposing to me.
What's that?
It's for Wesley, from Jack.
I'd forgotten it.
Maybe I was just trying
to forget it.
Why?
Jack recorded
a holographic message for Wesley
just after he was born.
It was a gift for him
when he grew up.
Jack was going to make
many more of them.
He never had the chance.
Are you afraid
of what it might say?
No. I just don't know if it'll
do more harm than good.
Wesley's finally come to terms
with his father's death.
Wesley has a lot of questions
about his father.
Things that you can't answer
for him.
Perhaps seeing this
will help him
understand.
( instrument whirring )
WOMAN:
Check completed, sir.
MAN:
I have an intermittent failure
in response
to the azimuth step command.
We're checking.
LA FORGE:
Uh-huh.
SERGEY:
So we walk into the school
and we didn't know
what to expect.
Is Worf hurt?
Is he in some kind of trouble?
The door opens
and there is our little
seven-year-old sitting on a
chair
and glaring across the room
at five teenage boys
all of them
with bloody noses.
( chuckles )
And then the principal
looked up and said
"Please, tell me
he's an only child."
We have taken enough
of the Commander's time.
No, no, no, we're way
ahead of schedule here.
SERGEY:
I just wanted to tell him
the story about...
Enough stories, Sergey.
Okay, okay.
Enough stories.
Well, now, how about
giving us a look
at the new engine core?
I used to be a warp
field specialist
on the old Excelsior-class.
I'd be delighted.
Mrs. Rozhenko?
Oh, no, no, no,
you two go ahead.
Your father will be hours.
Worf, why don't you
show me the arboretum?
Commander La Forge,
call me when you...
When my father
wishes to leave.
I can find my own way.
Turbolift four is, uh...
just over there, right?
I have all the specs
and diagrams at home.
The theta-matrix
compositor makes
the recrystallization process
ten times more efficient
than the old
Excelsior-class ships.
Amazing.
Commander, if you have
a couple of minutes
there is something else
I want to ask you.
Sure, Chief.
It's about my son.
...and your friend Louis
wants you to contact him
as soon as you're settled.
Is he still trying to
raise the ocean floor?
Oh, yes,
he's very excited about it.
He's been made
a supervisor now
as his wife
is constantly reminding
anyone who'll listen.
And I see no good reason
why the Earth should have
another subcontinent.
It's really quite
exciting actually
if you understand
the potential
of exploring a new world
on our own planet.
Well, I'm afraid
that I do not understand
this potential.
The mayor wants
to give you a parade.
RENE:
Thank you.
A parade?
Give you the keys
to the city.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.
He just needs a little
arm-twisting, dear.
A little coaxing.
No, he does not.
I'm here to rest and spend
some time with my family.
Well, I've already
warned the mayor
not to make any plans
without talking to us.
Thank you.
So...
Salut.
This the '46?
Forty-seven.
You've been drinking too much
of that artificial stuff.
What do you call it?
Synthehol?
It's spoiled you.
Ruined your palate.
On the contrary.
I think that synthehol
heightens
one's appreciation
for the genuine article.
Mmm.
Delicious, Marie.
Thank you.
Leave it to Robert
to find
the best cook in France...
then marry her.
Yes. Sadly, cooking
is becoming a lost art.
That's your wretched
technology again.
Robert and I have had
more than a few
discussions about getting
a replicator in the house.
I remember
the same "discussions"
between Mother and Father.
Father understood
better than anybody else
the danger
of losing those values
which we hold most precious.
I don't see
that you have to lose anything
just by adding a convenience.
Well, you wouldn't.
But in my view
life is already too convenient.
This is a very old argument.
Hmm.
It is.
I wrote a report
on starships.
For school.
And he won a ribbon for it.
The teacher even said
it was one of the best
he'd ever heard.
Good for you, uncle.
You know what?
I once wrote a report
on starships
when I was about your age.
Did you win a ribbon, too?
I don't recall.
And I don't find your modesty
very convincing, brother.
Of course you won the ribbon.
You always did.
Well, do you still have it?
Hmm?
Your report.
No, I don't think so.
Well, I still have mine.
Why don't you go
and get it
and then you can read it
to your uncle.
It's hard enough
to protect him...
To protect him
from all that's out there
without you encouraging him.
( spoon clinks on bowl )
I'm not encouraging him.
But if you weren't
so narrow-minded
if you allowed him to see
the world as it really is...
Well, you raise your own sons
as you would wish
and allow me
to do the same with mine.
MAN:
Ah, one man's idea
of paradise.
PICARD:
No, my dear Louis,
two men--
Robert's and my father's.
( Louis laughs )
Never did I know anyone
less interested in grapes
than you, Jean-Luc.
Oh, no, not true.
I was interested.
And I was proud that
my family were helping
to preserve the traditions.
I just didn't feel bound
by those traditions.
You always reach
for the future
and your brother
for the past.
There should be room
for both in this life.
And what about you,
you old rascal?
You've taken quite a shift
into the future yourself.
Well, hydroponics turned
out to be so dull.
Well, you should
have listened to me
at the beginning.
If I had listened to you,
I never would have
taken that cycling trip
with the Bloom sisters.
And broken your leg?
And got married-- twice.
I hear you've been promoted
to supervisor
of the Atlantis Project.
I am one of 200 supervisors
although my wife
would have you believe
I run the entire project.
Well, it's certainly
very exciting work.
I've kept up on it
in the journals.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
It's only...
There's just one thing
I don't understand.
You were such
a rotten swimmer, Louis.
( both laugh )
Thinking of you working
on the ocean floor...
I suppose we all find ways
to confront our greatest fears.
Seriously, how do you plan
to accelerate the buildup
on the underside of the mantle
without increasing the stress
on the tectonic plates?
Oh, you really have
kept up, haven't you?
Well, the truth is,
we don't know-- yet.
On the Enterprise,
we used harmonic resonators
to relieve the tectonic
pressures on Drema IV.
Obviously, it's not
the same problem...
You know, it's
such a shame.
The government is looking
for someone to take
over the project.
A real leader who'll go in
there and get things moving
and they are looking for
you, Jean-Luc.
But I know, I know, you'd
never leave Starfleet.
No, I'd never
leave Starfleet.
That's what I thought.
But, if nothing else
why don't I
send over some of
the internal studies
on the tectonic problem
since you're interested.
We could use any thoughts
you might have.
All right.
It's a great crew, son,
and they think the world of you.
They really do.
Mother, Father, I...
I wish you would be
a little more... reserved
while you are
on board.
I know.
We go too far
sometimes.
We're just excited
to be here.
Riker to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here.
I need to talk to you
about the phaser test results.
On my way,
Commander.
Have Guinan call me
if you need anything.
Maybe we should
just leave it alone.
I can't just
leave it alone.
I'm his mother.
GUINAN:
You know, sooner or later,
everyone comes in here.
They stand by those windows
and they look out
and they stare.
And they're looking
for that
little star
they call home.
It doesn't matter
how far away it is.
Everybody looks anyway.
I'm Guinan.
How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
You're Worf's parents.
Sergey and Helena
Rozhenko.
Welcome.
Sit, please.
Thank you.
( sighs )
There's something I
would like to ask you.
Please.
How come you never
gave him prune juice?
I beg your pardon?
Well, he said
he'd never had it
till he came here.
Now he can't get enough of it.
Worf?
He never wanted
any human food
while he was growing up.
Everything had to be Klingon.
HELENA:
I learned to cook
rokeg blood pie.
However we never
quite learned
how to eat it.
It was a difficult adolescence.
But you got through it.
We didn't do
anything special.
Didn't you?
Just look at him.
I think he's pretty special.
We knew it wouldn't
be easy for him
growing up
without other Klingons
to turn to for guidance.
We had to let him discover
and explore his heritage
by himself.
Let him find his own path.
So many parents
could learn so much
from the two of you.
Well...
I'm afraid that Worf feels
that we do not understand him.
Well, part of him
may feel that way.
But there's another part
that I've seen.
The part that comes in
and drinks prune juice.
The part that looks
out the window
towards home.
But he's not looking
towards the Klingon Empire.
He's looking towards you.
( footsteps approaching )
Jean-Luc?
Are you all right?
I seem to have made a rather
disturbing discovery.
Louis mentioned that
the Atlantis Project
needed a director...
and I found myself
actually thinking about it.
Why shouldn't you?
Oh...
Leaving my career,
the Enterprise...
Considering what you've
just been through...
No, no, no, it's not that.
Or is it?
Besides,
it would be wonderful
to have you back home.
Given a little time,
maybe you and your brother
might even get
to like one another.
Well, I already like
his choice in wives.
I never thanked you
for your correspondence.
It made me feel like
part of the family.
( doorbell dinging )
You're not like
part of the family.
You are part of the
family, Jean-Luc Picard.
Don't worry, dear.
I've got it.
Robert.
Louis, come in.
Let me get you some wine.
You can talk business.
Business?
Well, there's nothing
much to talk about.
I'm interested to know
what you thought
of our plans.
Well, I've only had a
chance to glance at them.
Uh, I've had a few ideas...
Wonderful.
We should discuss them
with the board of governors.
I've set up a meeting.
A meeting?
Just a preliminary
conversation.
Tomorrow morning?
Preliminary to what?
They want you.
I mentioned your interest
in the project, that's all.
That's all I had to say.
They jumped
at the prospect.
I never said
there was a prospect.
At least listen
to them, Jean-Luc.
All right, good.
Very good. Fine.
I'll listen to them.
You won't regret it,
Jean-Luc.
I promise you.
I'll see you
in the morning.
WESLEY:
I don't understand, Mom.
What kind of message?
I don't know exactly.
Your father made it a few weeks
after you were born.
Why?
He felt it was important
to say certain things.
And to make sure that he didn't
forget to tell you them later.
Do you know
what it says?
No.
But he wanted you
to have this
when you turned 18.
And I want you
to have it, too.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Are we disturbing you?
No, no.
I thought you were going
to your quarters
to sleep.
We just came by
to tuck you in.
Please.
When I heard you were
on the visitors' list
I was not sure
I wanted you to come.
I am glad you are here.
We had to come.
Our boy
was in trouble.
After we read your letter
about the discommendation
from the Klingons...
HELENA:
We didn't exactly
understand it all.
We didn't have to.
We know what kind
of man you are.
Whatever you did
we know it was
for a good reason.
I must bear my dishonor alone.
That is not true.
I'm sorry if this
is too human of us
but whatever
you are suffering
you must remember
we are with you.
And that
we're proud of you.
And that we love you.
You are our son.
ROBERT ( quietly ):
♪ Qu'il fait bon, fait bon... ♪
Careful.
You're not used to drinking
the real thing.
This, uh, synthehol
never leaves you
out of control.
Is that so?
That's so.
Well, this will.
Now, there is something
I'd like to see.
What's that?
The gallant captain
out of control.
Mind if I ask you
a question?
What the devil
happened to you up there?
Is this brotherly concern?
No.
Curiosity.
What did they do to you?
You know what happened.
Not precisely.
I gather you were hurt,
humiliated.
I've always thought you needed
a little humiliation.
Or was it humility?
Either would do.
ROBERT:
Why do you walk away?
That isn't your style.
PICARD:
I'm tired of fighting
with you, Robert.
Tired?
That's right!
Yes, tired
of the Enterprise, too?
The great Captain Picard
of Starfleet falls to Earth
ready to... plunge
into the water with Louis.
That isn't the brother
that I remember.
Still, I suppose
it must have seemed
like an ideal
situation, hmm?
Local boy makes good
returns home
after 20 years
to a hero's welcome.
I'm not a hero.
Of course you are.
Admit it.
You've never settled
for less than that
and you never will.
That's not true.
Cancel the parade?
In your favor?
No!
I never... I never
sought that rubbish.
Never sought?
Never sought president
of the school, valedictorian
athletic hero with your
arms raised in victory?
Valedictorian.
Arms raised
in victory...
Were you so jealous?
Yes, damn it!
I was always so jealous,
and I had a right to be!
A right?
I was always your brother.
Watching you receive the cheers.
Watching you break every rule
our father made
and get away with it.
Why didn't you
break a few rules?
Because I was
the elder brother
the responsible one.
It was my job
to look after you.
Look after me?
You? You were a bully!
Sometimes... maybe.
Sometimes I even enjoyed
bullying you.
All right, try it now.
Why did you come back,
Jean-Luc?
Did you come back
because you wanted me
to look after you again?
Damn you!
( groaning )
( growling )
( laughing )
Oh.
You were asking
for it, you know.
Yes, but you needed it.
You have been terribly hard
on yourself.
You don't know, Robert.
You don't know.
They took everything I was.
They used me to kill
and to destroy
and I couldn't stop them.
I should have been
able to stop them.
I tried.
I tried so hard.
But I wasn't strong enough.
I wasn't good enough!
I should have been able
to stop them.
I should...
So...
my brother is a human being
after all.
This is going
to be with you
a long time, Jean-Luc.
A long time.
You have to learn
to live with it.
You have a simple choice now--
live with it
below the sea with Louis
or above the clouds
with the Enterprise.
You know, I think
you were right after all.
I think I did come back
so that you could help me.
Do you know what?
I still don't like you,
Jean-Luc.
( chuckles )
MEN ( drunkenly ):
♪ Auprès de ma blonde ♪
♪ Qu'il fait bon,
fait bon, fait bon ♪
♪ Auprès de ma blonde ♪
♪ Qu'il fait bon, fait bon ♪
♪ Au... dum, da-da blonde ♪
♪ Qu'il... bo-bo fait bon... ♪
What in the world...?
♪ ...blonde... ♪
♪ Qu'il fait bon, fait bon... ♪
( humming )
What happened here?
( singing stops )
Uh...
Well, it's...
It's, uh...
it's entirely
my fault, Marie.
ROBERT:
Yes, uh, I fell down,
and then he fell down...
And then we both
fell down together.
We both... we both...
We both fell down
to-to-together.
Have you two
been fighting?
Fighting?
No. No.
No. Certainly not.
Shame on you both.
What would your father say
if he saw you like this?
He'd probably send us both
to bed without any supper.
Well, perhaps
it's just as well
you got it out
of your systems.
Perhaps it was, Marie.
Perhaps it was.
I'll contact Louis
and cancel the meeting
with the board
of governors.
It's time
that I was going.
Already, Jean-Luc?
Uh-huh.
The ship will be ready
to leave orbit soon
and I belong aboard.
If I should ever
doubt that again
I know where to come.
Computer.
Load program, Crusher one.
Program complete.
Enter when ready.
Run program.
Hello, Wesley.
As I make this recording
you are about
ten weeks old.
I wanted you to know
who I am today.
You see, this Jack
Crusher won't exist
by the time you're
all grown up.
I'll be older,
more experienced
and hopefully
a little wiser.
But this person
will be gone.
And I want you to know
who your father was
when you came
into the world.
When I see you lying
there in your crib
I realize I don't
know the first thing
about being a father.
So let me just apologize
for all the mistakes
I'm about to make
as you grow up.
I hope you don't grow
up resenting the fact
that I was gone so much.
That comes with
this uniform.
I don't know if I can explain
why Starfleet means
so much to me.
Maybe you'll understand
when you get
this recording.
Maybe you'll even want
to try one of these on.
But you'll probably
be a doctor
like your mother.
You're only a baby,
but it's remarkable.
I can see in your face
all the people I've
loved in my lifetime--
your mother
my father and mother--
our family.
I can see me in you, too.
And I can feel
that you're my son.
I don't know how
to describe it
but there's this...
connection.
This bond.
I'll always be a part
of you, Wesley.
( chuckles )
Well, I hope this makes
some sense to you.
I'm not sure that
it does to me.
But maybe I'll do
better next time.
I love you, Wesley.
Good-bye, Dad.
Come back and see us again.
Good-bye, Jean-Luc.
And be careful.
Take care... Uncle.
You, too.
Someday, I'll be leaving
for my starship, too.
Well, there's plenty
of time for that.
You may decide
to do something else
as you get older.
Jean-Luc, here is
a little of the '47.
Do not drink it all at once.
And if possible
try not to drink it alone.
Is there anything
you want us
to send you
from home?
No.
Perhaps some
of your rokeg blood pie.
Mmm, it's been a while
but I think
I still remember how.
Oh.
Ah, Captain.
Welcome back.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
These are my parents,
Helena and Sergey Rozhenko.
Delighted.
Sir.
Quite a ship you
have here, Captain.
You had the full tour,
I trust.
Well, actually, there
are still a few areas
because of the repairs...
Sergey, it's time to go.
SERGEY:
Yes, yes.
Yes, okay.
I have all the specs
and diagrams at home.
He's still out there.
Mm-hmm.
Dreaming about starships
and adventures.
It's getting late.
Yes.
But let him dream, hmm?