Captain's Log,
Stardate 44085.7.
Due to a medical emergency
we have been forced
to cut short
a two-day liberty on Ogus II
and set course
for Starbase 416.
It seems a young man's
practical joke
has come dangerously close
to a lethal conclusion.
Well, Mr. Potts.
Why don't we start
at the beginning?
We were at the arcade, sir
an-and I brought
this balloon with me
filled with red pillion dye.
You see, Willie's always
making fun of me.
I figured I'd
get him back...
Hey, hey,
slow down.
We programmed the game
for an ordinary laser duel.
You know, 21 points.
Four points for...
Yes, I'm familiar with the game.
Go on.
We went out to the forest
behind the east arcade.
I told Willie that his laser
pistol looked kind of funny
almost like a real one.
When I went behind the trees
I put the balloon into my vest,
and then...
And then you made
your nine-year-old brother
believe that he'd killed you.
Yes, sir.
And then he ran away?
And while he was hiding,
he ate the fruit of
a cove palm.
It was just a joke, sir.
I didn't think
this was going to happen.
Are you aware
of the infectious nature
of the parasites
which inhabit the cove palm?
I-I am now, sir.
Are you also familiar
with the terms
that I agreed to keep you
boys on the Enterprise
when your parents
went on sabbatical?
Tha-That we'd stay
out of trouble, sir.
Mr. Data?
DATA:
On my way, sir.
Think about it, Mr. Potts.
And while you're at it think
about what may have happened
had we not been this close
to a Starbase medical facility.
Were you able to contact
the boys' parents?
They have been
made fully aware of
the situation, sir.
RIKER:
Good... Escort this young man
to the quarantine anteroom.
Perhaps he could assist us
in lifting
his brother's spirits.
Aye, sir.
H-He really could die.
Fortunately
we are only two days
away from Starbase 416
and their laboratory
can isolate...
( click )
Can isolate what, sir?
Their laboratory can
isolate what, Commander?
Sir, I know I
made a mistake
and I can tell
you're angry
but if you're not
going to talk to me...
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Back so soon, Mr. Data?
La Forge to Bridge.
PICARD:
Go ahead, Commander.
Captain, we've completed our
dilithium vector calibrations.
We are currently at warp 4.5.
You're clear to increase
to warp seven.
Very good, Geordi.
Let me know if you...
Captain, did you
request a course
correction?
I didn't say we could
increase speed to warp 9.1, sir.
New course set
for heading 341 mark 221.
Course set by whom?
Not by me, Commander.
What's going on?
Data, who programmed
the new coordinates?
WESLEY:
Warp 9.3, Commander.
LA FORGE:
I don't advise this, Captain.
If we're going to maintain
our realignment progressions
we shouldn't be pushing warp
eight for at least an hour.
Commander.
( alarm sounds )
COMPUTER:
Evacuate Bridge.
Deck one life-support failure
in 30 seconds.
Turbolifts two, three, four,
everyone.
Transfer helm to Engineering,
Geordi.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
La Forge, let's get
a diagnostic sweep underway.
COMPUTER:
Evacuate Bridge.
Deck one life-support failure
in 20 seconds.
Reassemble
in Engineering.
COMPUTER:
Evacuate Bridge.
Deck one life-support failure
in ten seconds.
( alarm continues )
COMPUTER:
Deck one life-support
has been terminated.
Our velocity is holding
steady at warp 9.3.
Do you wish to
override, Commander?
No, not yet.
Computer, isolate cause
of life-support failure.
Atmosphere conditioning pumps
on deck one
are operating in negative mode.
How can that be?
There are seven independent
safety interlocks to
prevent that.
Captain, I believe
we've found the problem
but it really doesn't
make sense.
Bring the Enterprise
to a full stop, Commander.
Aye, sir.
Full stop, Ensign.
It's not responding, sir.
I'm going to have to do this
at a manual input level, sir.
Wes.
We're still at the altered
heading, Captain.
Holding at warp 9.3.
WORF:
Captain.
Force fields have been
established
on all Main Bridge turbolift
doors and service crawlways.
Computer, locate
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Commander Data
is on the Main Bridge.
What the hell
is he up to?
Number One, take a security team
up to deck two.
Try and break through
from below.
Commander.
Everything's locked up, Captain.
We have no control
of impulse
or warp engines from here.
Navigation's not
responding either, sir.
Picard to Main Bridge.
Commander Data, do you hear me?
I repeat.
Mr. Data, do you hear...?
( cutoff beep )
Computer, recognize Data,
Lieutenant Commander.
Alpha One clearance.
Priority clearance recognition,
Alpha One.
Maintain minimum auxiliary power
and disengage
subspace communication.
Acknowledged.
He is on the Bridge, sir.
Mr. La Forge...
prepare for saucer separation.
Sir, we're
at warp 9.3.
I am aware of the risks, Ensign.
When the umbilical splits
we should regain
primary control.
Do you agree?
Yes, sir.
The saucer module should fall
out of warp within two minutes.
Be prepared to sweep back
and pull it in
with a tractor beam.
Aye, sir.
Initiate auto sequence.
( in Picard's voice):
Computer, recognize Picard,
Jean-Luc.
Alpha Two clearance.
Priority clearance recognition,
Alpha Two.
Cancel separation sequence.
Sequence canceled.
Isolate all remaining
command functions
and accept related orders
and inquiries
from Main Bridge only.
( console beeping )
The separation sequence
has been aborted, Captain.
Computer, recognize Jean-Luc
Picard, Alpha Two priority
and re-establish separation
procedure immediately.
Orders regarding
command functions
are no longer accepted
from your present location.
And just what location
are they accepted from?
Interface terminals
on Main Bridge only.
You're the only one
who has clearance
to localize
command functions.
It seems Commander Data
has acquired it as well.
WORF:
The isolinear subprocessor
extends 3.5 meters.
RIKER:
I've got a clear path
to panel J14-Baker.
What's that going
to do for us?
J14-Baker backs onto Science
Station Two, Commander.
Have they re-inverted
the environmental
control sequencer?
Yes, sir. Life-support
has been re-established.
Then you and Casey
get up here.
Let's get to it.
( in normal voice ):
Computer, configure
a perimeter field charge
sections 9-K through 12-T.
( electronic buzzing )
RIKER:
What the hell was that?
WORF:
He's activated
a force field, sir.
RIKER:
Great. Just great.
Chief O'Brien.
Yes, Captain?
We had better disable the site
to site transporter function.
When we get wherever we're going
I don't want Mr. Data
beaming off the Bridge.
I'll get right to it, sir.
Doctor Crusher?
Yes, Captain.
Is your quarantine intact?
So far, Sick Bay force fields
don't seem
to have been affected.
The boy?
He's all right.
But he's not going
to stay all right.
Sir, we have to get this ship
to a Starbase medical facility.
It seems, Doctor
that Mr. Data
has other plans
for the Enterprise right now.
Oh, come on, I
can't believe that.
Everybody's played
a practical joke
on somebody at one
time or another.
Not me.
Not even a little one?
How about April Fools'?
I can't believe that
you're telling me
that you've never tried
to pull something
even on April Fools' Day?
What for?
It's never funny
to the one getting fooled.
Well, I'm sure
your brother didn't intend
for it to get
this out of hand.
Certainly not to
the degree it has.
Take a deep breath.
What's so funny about making
someone think you killed them?
Take a deep breath.
Have you been
drinking all the
water I asked you to?
Yes.
Well, keep it up.
There might be
a slight delay
in reaching Starbase,
and I want...
There. You see?
How can I tell him when he's
not going to listen to me?
Why don't you try, Jake?
It's just a waste
of time.
He won't listen.
Computer, prepare
to transport me directly
to the following coordinates.
Site-to-site
transport interlocks
have been manually deactivated.
Can you override?
Negative.
Show me the shortest route
to Transporter Room One.
Computer, prepare to activate
cascade force field sequence
in the following progression.
LA FORGE:
No matter what we try
the computer
will only accept
commands from the Bridge, sir.
He has blocked every
subspace channel, sir.
We cannot even
call for help.
Have you tried tracing back
navigation inputs?
We don't even know what
star system we're in, sir.
The only way we knew
we'd come out of warp
was by looking
out a window.
O'Brien to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Chief.
Captain, he's up to something.
What now?
He discovered
the site-to-site lockout.
I wouldn't be surprised
if he tried to
make it to
a transporter room now.
Mr. Worf, I want security teams
along all the main passageways
and in every transporter room.
And see if the computer
will be good enough
to give us
the precise stun setting
to disable Mr. Data.
Yes, sir.
Computer, estimate the time
from this location
to Starbase 416 at warp nine.
Inquiries regarding
command functions
are no longer accepted
from your present location.
( in Picard's voice):
Computer
establish a security code
for access to all functions
previously transferred
to Bridge.
Enter code.
1-7-3-4-6-7-3-2-1-4-7-6-
Charlie-3-2-7-8-9-7-7-7-
6-4-3-Tango-7-3-2-
Victor-7-3-1-1-7-8-8-8-
7-3-2-4-7-6-7-8-9-
7-6-4-3-7-6-Lock.
Security code intact for all
specified inquiries and orders.
Computer,
initiate cascade sequence
accepting instructions
from Commander Data en route...
now.
LA FORGE:
He's out.
Security team
approaching location.
Intersection 8-J,
aft-port.
Establish.
I order you to stop!
Computer
begin scan-phase.
No, no, it's too close.
This has gone
far enough, Data.
Computer, three-meter
cross-seal.
I wouldn't
advise that, sir.
The phase coils don't take well
to ricochets.
What's he doing?
He's reactivating the site-
to-site transport interlocks.
Does that mean
he'll be able to...?
( insects chirping,
birds calling )
( liquids bubbling )
( electrical buzzing )
( chuckling )
Oh...
Uh-huh.
You're right on time.
Open.
One of these...
( ratcheting clicks )
and one of these...
There... you... are.
I fail to recall
how I arrived here.
I sent for you.
( chuckling ):
In a manner of speaking.
And who are you, sir?
( laughing )
Data to Enterprise.
Enterprise, do you read me?
I always loved
that face.
Please, sit down.
We were headed
for a medical facility.
I was taking the boy's brother
to Sick Bay, and...
I'm sure
your starship
will be back for you soon.
Please, sit down.
I must find a way
to contact the Enterprise.
Tell me
do I look somewhat,
uh... familiar to you?
You do bear a resemblance
to Dr. Noonien Soong,
the cyberneticist who...
( chuckling )
who constructed me.
But Dr. Soong was killed
shortly afterward
by the Crystalline Entity.
Ah, there we are.
This is your lucky day, Data.
You found your long lost father,
and he's alive.
What do you think of that?
But the colony was destroyed.
There were no survivors.
I, uh...
I never felt too comfortable
living anywhere without
a pre-arranged route of escape.
I admit, I, uh...
I wouldn't have guessed
I'd be running
from a giant snowflake, but...
It is really you.
LA FORGE:
Captain
the quarantine field
in Sick Bay.
You have
access to it?
When he transferred force field
control to the Bridge
he must have only specified
the fields he was
planning to initiate.
The quarantine field
was already operating.
LA FORGE:
Under normal circumstances
we could divert
that field energy
and use it to cancel the force
field protecting the Bridge.
But we have to retain
the medical quarantine.
Determine the absolute minimum
field energy Dr. Crusher needs
and use the rest
to get me onto my Bridge.
How are you
this morning?
Not so great.
I'm having trouble
standing up.
I get sort of dizzy.
You heard the old story
about the man
who goes to his doctor?
He says, "Doctor, it hurts
when I raise my arm like this."
The Doctor says, "Then don't
raise your arm like that."
So... if I get dizzy
standing up...
Then don't stand up.
( door opens )
Okay, Doc,
we're ready.
If all goes well, you
shouldn't notice a thing.
Make sure it goes well,
Commander.
Your brother tells me
that you still
won't speak to him.
So?
It's hard
on him, too.
He feels very guilty
about what happened.
He's your brother.
Why is everyone so worried
about him?
I'm the one who's sick.
I'm the one who's going to die.
Hey, nobody is going
to die, Willie.
Do you hear me?
Nobody.
Captain, we are in.
PICARD:
We're on our way, Lieutenant.
Computer,
restore Tactical Station.
Deactivation of command
function overrides
requires Alpha Two clearance.
Beverly thinks it's
going to be tight.
Let's hope he didn't take
us too far off course.
Let's hope.
It won't answer
to my clearance, sir.
Computer, this is
Captain Picard.
Return all command
functions to
their stations.
Alpha Two clearance recognized.
Please enter security code.
Security code?
Data.
I was afraid
of something like this.
Sensors are operative.
Well, at least
that's something.
What have you got?
No fix on Data.
But I am picking up
a single life-form
on the surface, sir.
It appears human.
That's a human that has the
answers to a lot of questions.
Something else.
What is it?
A small vessel.
Entering orbit.
I detect no life-forms
aboard, sir.
Mm-hmm. Good.
( chuckling ):
Good, good, good.
Keep it up,
keep it up.
Old Tom Handy swore
you'd never master that.
Data, Data, whistle for me.
( whistling
"Pop Goes the Weasel" off-key)
Oh. Oh, well.
All right, that's enough.
Sit down, sit down.
Ah, beautiful, beautiful.
You know, I've been able
to keep track of you
from time to time.
You've become
something of a celebrity
in cybernetic circles.
Uh, Data, why Starfleet?
Sir?
I gave you the ability
to choose
whatever you wanted.
To do whatever you wanted.
Why Starfleet?
It was Starfleet officers
who rescued me.
Oh, so you decided
to emulate your
emancipators, huh?
How disappointing.
What choice of vocation
would have met
with your approval, sir?
Well, I often hoped
you might...
become a scientist.
Perhaps even
a cyberneticist.
To follow in your footsteps,
as it were.
I see nothing
wrong with that.
May I ask you a question, sir?
Certainly.
Anything
you like.
Why did you create me?
Why does a
painter paint?
Hmm?
Why does a boxer box?
You know what Michelangelo
used to say?
That the sculptures he made
were already there
before he started,
hidden in the marble.
All he needed to do
was... ( whistles )
remove the unneeded bits.
Wasn't quite that easy
with you, Data.
But the need to do it,
my need to do it
was no different
than Michelangelo's need.
Now let me ask you a question.
Why are humans
so fascinated by old things?
Old things?
Old buildings,
churches, walls.
Ancient things.
Antique things.
Tables, clocks, knickknacks.
Why? Why? Why?
There are many
possible explanations.
If you brought a Noophian
to Earth
he'd probably look around
and say
"Tear that old village down.
"It's hanging in rags.
Build me something... something
new, something efficient."
But to a human
that... that old house,
that ancient wall...
that's a shrine.
Something to be cherished.
Again, I ask you, why?
Perhaps, for humans
old things represent
a tie to the past.
Well, what's so important
about the past?
People got sick,
they needed money.
Why tie yourself to that?
Humans are mortal.
They seem to need a sense
of continuity.
Aha. Hmm...
Why?
To give their lives meaning,
a sense of purpose.
Oh. Well.
And, uh, this continuity--
does it only run one way?
Backwards... to the past?
I suppose it is a factor
in the human desire
to procreate.
Oh, so you believe
that having children
gives humans a sense
of immortality,
do you?
It is a reasonable explanation
to your query, sir.
And to yours,
as well, Data.
( door opens )
Lore!
Looks like we have ourselves
a... family reunion.
Open.
DATA:
I implore you
do not reactivate him.
Don't be
ridiculous, Data.
Lore is far from
the maniacal android
you have made him out to be.
In any case, he'll obey me.
He always did.
But he admitted
to an alliance
with the Crystal Entity.
To gain its favor,
he betrayed the colonists
and would have betrayed
the Enterprise as well,
had I not...
Shh.
One more.
That should do it.
Shh, shh-shh-shh.
So... you're still alive.
I'm surprised
you woke me.
Why didn't you just
take me apart again
and be done with it?
That is why the two of you
captured me, isn't it?
SOONG:
Data had nothing
to do with this, Lore.
And nobody captured you.
Not exactly, that is.
You see, both of your brains
contain a simple homing device.
Data's was activated
purposefully.
Yours... Well, until you
walked through that door
I had no idea you'd
ever been reassembled.
No thanks to you.
But thanks to you
dear Brother,
I spent nearly
two years drifting in space.
If it hadn't been
for a fortunate encounter
with a Pakled trade ship,
I'd still be out there.
I had no alternative.
You would have destroyed
the Enterprise.
Well, since I seem to be
an uninvited guest
at your little party
I'll leave you
with your beloved son
and be on my way.
SOONG:
Lore, wait.
There are questions
I can answer.
You'll have no chance
to ask them later.
You see, I'm dying.
Yeah, I'm dying.
Dying from what, sir?
Wait a minute.
What... what do you mean,
you're dying?
You look fine.
You're not that old.
You... you look fine.
What is this?
Some kind of a trick?
I wish it were.
We have control
of sensors
life-support and
auxiliary power, Captain.
Nothing more.
The code, Mr. La Forge?
We can't even locate
the file address.
At least, that would tell us
how many digits
we're talking about.
Not that it would
really help much.
I want something
that will really help.
CRUSHER:
And quickly, too.
Willie Potts has
24 hours, 36 tops.
If it goes much
longer than that
the only thing left
for Starbase 416
will be to do a postmortem.
Geordi, if the
computer's programmed
to allow Data
to transport down
it would figure
that it would allow him
to beam back up, right?
It would figure.
And Data would have
left a trace imprint
when he beamed down?
Sure, everybody does.
So, what would be involved
in pulling that trace
and finding a way to
make the computer think
someone else is Data?
Maybe a few
someone elses?
( sighs )
We'd have to access
the transport controller
and reset it to a testing mode.
Convince it that it's
still back in school
accepting simulated inputs.
That's not going to be easy
without the main computer
but I suppose we could network
a few tricorders together.
Try, Mr. La Forge.
Yes, sir.
You did what you had to do?
What kind of an answer
is that?
The only one I can give you.
You were not
functioning properly.
Lore told me
the colonists envied him
because you made him
so completely human.
I wouldn't exactly have used
the word "envious," Data.
You disassembled me.
You took me apart.
Lore also told me
that the colonists
petitioned you to replace him
with a less perfect android.
Oh...
The last thing you should
think of yourself as, Data
is less perfect.
The two of you are virtually
identical, except for a bit
of programming.
It was a lie.
Another lie.
I would have proven myself
worthy to you
if you'd just given me a chance.
But it was easier
just to turn your back
and build your precious Data.
You were the first.
You meant as much
to me as Data ever did
but you were unstable.
The colonists were not
envious of you.
They were afraid of you.
You were unstable.
I am not
less perfect than Lore.
Why didn't you just fix me?
It was within your power
to fix me.
It wasn't as easy as that.
The next... the next logical
step was to construct Data.
Afterward, I planned to get
back to you, to-to fix you.
"Next logical step."
I am not less perfect than Lore.
( mocking Data ):
"I am not less perfect
than Lore."
Enough!
Both of you, sit down.
Sit down.
( sighs )
For all these years, I've been
plagued by what went wrong.
With all of your
complexities, Lore
your nuances...
basic emotion seemed
almost simple by comparison.
But the emotion
turned and twisted
became entangled
with ambition.
Lore...
if I had known you were
no longer sitting in pieces
on some distant shelf,
if I had known
tha-that I could simply press
a button and bring you here
I would have spent those years
trying to make things right
for you as well.
But all I knew of was Data.
So I worked long
and hard.
Yes.
And now I believe
I've succeeded.
This... this...
this... is why I've brought
you here, Data.
Basic emotions.
Simple feelings, Data.
Your feelings.
I've imagined
how hard it's been for you
living amongst beings
so moved by emotion.
I don't have to imagine.
I know how hard it's been.
You'll be surprised, Data.
Feelings do
funny things.
You may even learn to...
understand your evil brother.
To forgive him.
We will be more alike, Data,
you and I.
You'll see.
I'm... I'm happy for you.
I question your sincerity, Lore.
Well, perhaps with this
you'll learn
to be more trusting, Data.
Your brother has had good reason
to be bitter.
But, sir, Lore was
responsible for...
He wasn't given the chance
that you and I were given--
to live.
But now, I'm sure he understands
why I did
what I had to do.
If there were only time, Lore.
What a shame.
The procedure is quite simple,
hmm, but I'm tired.
I need to rest first.
I'm tired.
They're sure this
is going to work?
Nobody knows
the transporters
better than O'Brien
and La Forge.
They tell me they've managed
more than a little
sleight of hand with our
authorization codes.
They can insert them
into the recall loop?
The computer should think
all three of us are Data.
I just hope we don't
all beam back
looking like Data.
Whenever
you say, sir.
Bring him home,
Number One.
Energize.
Data?
♪ The sons of the Prophet
were valiant and bold ♪
♪ And quite unaccustomed
to fear ♪
♪ But of all the most reckless,
or so I am told ♪
( chuckles )
♪ was Abdul Abulbul Amir ♪
How do you feel?
I've always loved that ditty
but I could never quite get
the cadence right.
Thank you, Father.
You called me Father.
Well, what would you prefer
I called you?
Often-Wrong?
What did Lore tell you
about that?
That is what the colonists
called you, isn't it?
Often-Wrong Soong.
It is a very sloppy rhyme.
Wrong Soong? Wrong Soong?
I-I-It just doesn't work.
Let's see...
Data, how are
you feeling?
Often-Wrong's
got a broken heart.
Can't even tell his boys apart.
Lore.
( laughing )
Well, well, well,
well, well, well.
You're not as feeble
as I thought you were.
This won't work.
Those circuits--
they weren't designed for you.
Where's Data?
"Where's Data?"
You didn't fill Data
with substandard parts
did you, old man?
No... that honor
was bestowed upon me.
You owe me, old man.
Not him, me.
It wasn't meant for you.
You're not listening to me.
It must be removed.
Nice try, Often-Wrong.
Nice try.
( gasps )
I don't know exactly
what it's doing
but it's doing something.
I didn't know you were alive.
If I had...
( Soong cries out,
glass shatters )
♪ There were brave men
aplenty ♪
♪ All well known to fame ♪
♪ Who served in the ranks
of the Czar ♪
♪ Ba-ba-ba, ba-ba-ba, ba,
ba, ba, ba, ba, ba... ♪
The human is here.
And Data?
No way of knowing.
Set them on stun.
Down here.
It's all right.
Take it easy.
This...
this is Dr. Noonien Soong.
That's impossible.
Soong's dead.
No, I'm telling you,
look at this stuff.
It's Soong, all right.
Here. Let me.
( click )
Would you mind telling me
what's going on here?
He surprised me.
Commander.
What has happened here?
Doctor.
Dr. Soong?
So alike.
( chuckles ):
He saw...
I couldn't tell you apart.
There was
only one chip.
I tried to tell him...
but... I couldn't.
I wanted... I couldn't
build another one.
RIKER:
You tried to tell who?
Damn it, Data, what's going on?
Lore, sir.
He was inadvertently summoned
here by the same signal
which activated
my homing circuitry.
It seems that after
nearly two years
in interstellar
space, he was...
Mr. Data, there's
a very sick little boy
on board the Enterprise,
who's not getting any better.
We're dead in the water
until you get us out of here.
It's all right.
Access your third
nested memory file
and...
execute instruction 5155.
That will clear
your memory block.
I was unaware of having caused
any inconvenience, sir.
We'll discuss it later,
Mr. Data.
Doctor, you're coming
with us, too.
You need to get to Sick Bay.
( snorts )
Young man, I've lived here
a long time.
I have no plans
to die anywhere else.
But, sir, our medical facility
may be able to...
Go, go, go, go, Data, go.
Go with your friends.
May I say good-bye
to Dr. Soong, sir?
Alone, sir.
Everybody dies, Data.
Well, almost everybody.
Do you believe that we are
in some way alike, sir?
In many ways,
I'd like to believe.
Then it is all right
for you to die
because I will remain alive.
You know that I cannot
grieve for you, sir.
You will... in your own way.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Data.
Good-bye... Father.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44091.1.
We have been at Starbase 416
for three days.
Young Willie Potts is
responding well to treatment
and has been returned
to the Enterprise.
The transfer went well?
He'll remain in quarantine
for another week or two
but he's out
of the woods.
Splendid.
( roars )
Well, Mr. Data, I see your gifts
have been well received.
Yes, sir.
The boys appear to have
reconciled their differences.
They're
brothers, Data.
Brothers forgive.