Captain's Log,
Stardate 44143.7.
We have moved into Sector 21947
in response to a distress call
from a Talarian
observation craft.
The alien vessel appears
adrift, and our initial scans
have detected a
life-threatening radiation leak
within its propulsion system.
I get no further response
from the vessel.
Maintain
an open channel.
Dr. Crusher and
her assistants
are waiting in
Transporter Room Three.
Sir, may I remind
you that during the
Galen border conflict
it was a common tactic
of the Talarians
to abandon
their observation craft
rig them to self-destruct...
And issue
a general distress call.
Yes, Mr. Data, I know.
That particular
guerrilla maneuver
resulted in 219 fatalities
over a three-day period.
Is there any way to detect
their self-destruct device?
Negative, sir.
The Talarians employ
a subspace proximity detonator.
It is not detectable
by our scans.
Or the away team's tricorders.
Right.
Captain, the Talarian warship,
the Q'Maire is responding
to the distress call.
Position?
Halfway through
the Woden Sector.
It'll take them hours
to get here, sir,
even at maximum warp.
Counselor?
There is life onboard,
and it's fading.
Number One, assemble
the rest of your away team.
Prepare for immediate
rescue operations.
Yes, sir.
Ancillary power is failing.
( moaning )
They're nothing more
than children.
I am Commander Riker, of the
Federation Starship Enterprise.
We will evacuate you
and give you medical care.
You will not be harmed.
Enterprise, prepping
five Talarian males
for transport immediately
to Sick Bay.
Trauma team,
stand by to receive the injured.
We have
radiation burns
and possible
respiratory
distress.
TRANSPORTER OFFICER:
Transport locked in
and ready, Doctor.
Stand by for
my orders.
Captain, this appears to be
a basic training ship.
Five boys, all teens,
all wearing uniforms.
PICARD:
Proceed with the evacuation,
Number One.
No other life signs
aboard, sir.
Commander, quickly.
What is it?
This boy, he's human.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have completed
an emergency evacuation
of four Talarians
and one human.
How this young man
found himself
in the company of these aliens
remains a mystery.
It's Jono, right?
Is that what I heard
them call you?
I'm Dr. Crusher.
I'm just examining you
for radiation injuries.
It won't hurt.
I have a son
not much older than you.
Perhaps you'd like to meet him.
Hmm?
Well, Jono
you seem to have escaped
radiation damage.
Pretty lucky.
Dr. Crusher.
Now, how did this happen?
( wailing )
( all wailing )
What is it?
They're terrified.
( wailing )
They all just
started up.
Please, may I have
your attention?
( wailing continues )
Please, may I have
your attention?
Stop that immediately!
( wailing stops abruptly )
Well, that's better.
Now, what's your name,
young man?
He won't talk, Captain.
We haven't been able
to get through to him.
Captain.
I am Jono.
Take me home
to my Captain.
Take me home to Endar.
He managed to escape
radiation trauma
but the scan shows
something else.
What?
Two previously fractured ribs
a broken arm
and a low-grade concussion.
There might be
neurological impairment.
I'd like
to examine him further.
Jean-Luc, the Talarians
have been known
to be ruthless
to their enemies.
I think there's
a real possibility
they may have
brutalized the child.
Isn't it possible
that the injuries
were caused prior
to his captivity?
Hmm, not likely.
He's been with them
a long time--
long enough to assimilate
their cultural traits.
And calcium trace patterns
indicate
that the injuries took place
during the past seven years.
But if they have abused the boy
why would he so devoutly wish
to return to them?
Oh, it's not uncommon.
It was identified centuries ago
as the Stockholm Syndrome.
( grunting )
TROI:
Jono! What is it?
Get him! Get him!
Oh!
TROI:
Jono!
( grunts )
I just suggested
he take off his gloves.
Suddenly, he lost control.
Security, we need
some assistance down
here in Sick Bay.
Don't hurt him.
Hey, no.
Jono.
She won't leave
me alone.
She's keeps trying
to dissect me!
She was trying
to help you.
I don't want her help!
Send me back with my brothers!
Send us back to Captain Endar!
Jono, I want you to
stop this immediately!
Yes, Captain.
Good. That's better.
Now, if we're to
accomplish anything...
Data to Picard.
Go ahead.
We have received
a subspace communiqué
from Starfleet Command
regarding the young human, sir.
Very well.
Doctor, Counselor.
Lieutenant Worf
escort this young man
to quarters.
He is to be confined there
until further notice.
Yes, Doctor.
Why are you here,
Klingon, with them?
Did they capture
you, too?
They are not my captors.
They are my comrades.
Why do you take orders
from a female?
Dr. Crusher.
She is my superior officer.
Among my people, a female
can never outrank a man.
You are human.
And among humans
females can achieve
anything the males can.
I am no more human than you are.
I am Talarian.
You are confused.
( wailing )
Stop that!
( stops abruptly )
I will make the B'Nar--
the mourning--
until I am back
with my brothers.
( wailing )
( wailing stops and starts )
By matching DNA gene types
Starfleet was able to identify
the boy as Jeremiah Rossa.
Rossa?
As in Admiral
She is his grandmother,
Captain.
He was born 14 years ago
on the Federation colony,
Galen IV.
His parents, Connor
and Moira Rossa, were killed
three years, nine months later
when their colony was overrun
by Talarian forces.
I remember.
There were no survivors.
The boy was listed
as missing
and presumed dead.
I know another Rossa
who was killed in action
at the Krasner outpost.
Tragedy seems
to follow that family.
The Admiral lost
both her sons.
Well, now she'll
have something
to celebrate.
Captain, if Jeremiah
is returned
to his family in his
present condition
it will be a wrenching
experience for everyone
especially for him.
He needs to rediscover
his identity
make some connection
with his roots.
I agree.
Do what you can
to accomplish that, Counselor.
I don't think
I can do anything, Captain.
Why not?
CRUSHER:
Troi's right.
It's very clear that the boy
does not respond well to women.
The Talarians are a rigidly
patriarchal society, sir.
Jeremiah needs to build
a relationship with a man--
a father figure with whom
he can explore his origins.
And I think
it should be you, Captain.
Oh, no, Counselor.
Oh, no, Counselor,
I don't think so.
He needs someone
who is trained in these matters.
You are the only person
with whom he has shown
any connection.
If he is to find his... humanity
then you are the only one
who can help him.
It's up to you,
Captain.
( sighs )
( wailing )
Jono.
Jono, why do you make
that noise?
It is the custom of my people
when we are in distress.
Isn't it also
the custom of your people
to listen to the wishes
of their Captain?
Yes.
Then, as Captain
of the Starship Enterprise
I ask you
not to make that sound.
Yes, sir.
Oh, good.
Well, now that's cleared up
let's, um...
let's, uh...
let's get
acquainted, shall we?
Uh, what do you
think of your room?
I know it's, uh...
it's a little sterile
but if there's anything
you would like...
Um... pictures, perhaps?
Games?
This is a cage.
I'm still your captive.
Oh, no.
Not at all.
I thought
you'd be comfortable here.
Are you going to return me
to my Captain?
We will rendezvous
with the Warship Q'Maire
at 0740 hours.
We will transfer the Talarians
to Captain Endar.
Including me?
We'll discuss your situation
with Captain Endar.
I don't like this place.
We could find
some other quarters.
I've always lived
with my Captain.
Ah.
Yes, well,
that wouldn't work here.
Well, I'm sure you'll see
there's nothing
here to appeal to
a young person.
Put that down, please.
It's Klingon.
Yes. Would you put it back
where you got it?
Uh...
Well...
Here we are,
eh, Jono?
I notice you haven't taken off
your gloves.
Not here.
Why not?
So that I don't have to touch
an alien.
Jono, your Captain, Endar...
has he ever hurt you?
Inflicted pain?
Pain is not a consideration.
Then he has.
I did not say that.
Don't you understand?
Pain is not what matters.
Passing the tests is everything.
Is that what they are--
tests of pain?
You understand nothing.
It's true, I don't
fully understand Talarians
but you are not Talarian.
I will not listen to this.
I will not listen to your lies.
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
Yes, Counselor.
Please, come in.
Sit down.
You're probably not
aware of this
but I've never been
particularly comfortable
around children.
Really?
For some reason, they just
don't seem to respond to me.
I see.
Frankly, I think that my time
would be best served
carrying out the duties
and responsibilities
of a Starfleet Captain.
Seldom have I heard
an explanation so...
well-rehearsed.
Look, Counselor, I...
I just feel that I'm not
the right person for this job.
Strange, isn't it?
You'll travel light-years
dodge asteroid storms,
brave hostile aliens
and yet, when asked
to assume a parental
role, you cringe.
Why do you suppose
that is?
I'm not cringing.
I'm just...
acknowledging my limitations.
When you were a
child, did you
have any friends?
Other children you played with?
I don't think that this
has anything
to do with anything.
( clears throat )
Well, perhaps it was because...
This is foolish.
What were you
going to say?
It's just that...
ever since I was a child,
I've always known
exactly what I wanted to do--
be a member of Starfleet.
Nothing else mattered to me.
Virtually my entire youth
was spent
in the pursuit of that goal.
In fact...
I probably skipped my childhood
altogether.
You know, Captain
almost no one is born
being a good parent.
Most people just
have to muddle through
and do the best that they can.
Are you saying that's what
I'm going to have to do?
Yes.
And you might be surprised
at just how good you can be.
( sighs )
( muffled, discordant
string music playing )
( music playing loudly )
Computer!
Turn off that noise!
( music stops )
Computer, what...?
What was that?
The Alba Ra, a contemporary
Talarian musical form.
Jono?
Jono, where are you?
You turned off my music.
Yes, I most certainly did
and I expect it
to stay turned off.
Would you come down
from there?
I see you made yourself at home.
I cannot rest on your beds.
They hurt my back.
Will you come here?
There's something
I want to show you.
Those are Connor
and Moira Rossa.
They are your parents.
The baby...
is you.
Jeremiah Rossa.
My name is Jono.
Well, you were born Jeremiah
on Galen IV.
The colony was
destroyed later
during a border skirmish.
Hmm.
See?
You knew how to laugh once.
Do you remember
any of this, Jono?
Your parents, your home?
I know that Endar rescued me.
He told me so.
Jono, your parents were killed
by the Talarians.
It was war.
Death is part of war.
RIKER:
Captain?
Yes, what is it,
Number One?
We've established visual contact
with the Warship Q'Maire.
Endar!
Hey! Hey!
You... stay put.
I'm on my way,
Number One.
MAN:
Get to cover!
WOMAN:
I can't leave you!
( phasers zapping )
MAN:
Take Jeremiah.
Get to the forest.
I'll hold them off.
WOMAN:
No! No! Come with us!
MAN:
No!
BOY ( sobbing ):
Mama! Mama!
WOMAN ( sobbing ):
Jeremiah... Jeremiah!
( explosions and screams )
( boy sobbing )
Mama...
( sobbing fades )
Status, Mr. Data?
Q'Maire at station.
Holding steady at
bearing 013 mark 015.
Distance-- 506
kilometers.
Are its weapons systems active?
Negative, sir.
Captain Endar requests
an open channel, sir.
On screen.
I am Captain Endar
of the Warship Q'Maire.
To whom am I speaking?
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation Starship
Enterprise.
We have rescued
four crew members
from your observation craft.
They have received
medical attention.
They are ready for transport.
Your actions are duly noted.
We will forward coordinates
for immediate transport.
You're welcome, I'm sure.
One moment, Captain.
We've also discovered
a human among your crew.
Jono.
Actually, his name
is Jeremiah...
Jeremiah Rossa.
What is his condition?
Is he injured?
He was not wounded
in the mishap
but as a representative
of the Federation
I require an explanation.
Why has this child been
held in your custody
for so many years?
No explanation is warranted,
Captain.
He is my son.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Captain Endar's claim
that Jeremiah Rossa is his son
is clearly unacceptable.
However, to avoid
escalating tensions
I have invited
the Talarian leader
to come aboard the Enterprise
so that we may address
the issue face-to-face.
Yes, I was in charge
of the force
that repelled
the trespassers
on Galen IV.
I must say,
your Federation troops
fought tenaciously.
Among them,
Connor and Moira Rossa.
I suppose.
After the battle, I found
this squalling child
huddled by a body.
of a young woman,
his mother, presumably.
There was almost no one
left alive on Galen IV.
Was I to leave him screaming
over his mother's body?
You should have notified
the Federation authorities.
To conceal him was a clear
violation of our agreement.
I took him in accordance
with my people's traditions.
What tradition is it
that empowered you
to capture a helpless child?
I lost my son
at the hands of humans
during the conflict
over Castal I.
Talarian custom allows me
to claim the son
of a slain enemy.
Does that custom extend
to brutalizing
the surrogate son?
What are you talking about?
Our medical officer discovered
evidence of injuries so severe
they might be
considered torture.
Nonsense.
I've never harmed Jono.
Then explain the fractured ribs,
concussion, broken arm.
( laughs )
Broken arm.
Youth!
Have you ever
been a father, Picard?
Have you ever had a son
desperately trying
to win your approval,
your respect?
Jono broke his ribs
riding on a t'stayan.
Six hooves,
a very powerful beast.
The arm...
in a contest with other youths.
He endured the pain
and won
the competition.
One day, he will be
a great warrior.
Doesn't he deserve to
become more than that?
His true heritage
is human, Endar.
A heritage long
since forgotten.
While onboard,
you are welcome to supervise
the return of your crew
but I cannot allow
Jeremiah Rossa
to be returned to your custody.
His true family are waiting
for him on Earth.
Ah.
Then under no
circumstances
will I allow your ship
to leave our territory.
I have already reported
our position
and the nature
of this violation to Starfleet.
And I've already called
for reserve forces
into this sector.
Are you saying
that you are willing
to go to war over this boy?
Would you not,
for your only son?
We have been at peace
for many years.
Let us not rush
headlong into war.
Then help me
to avoid it.
If you will allow
me to see Jono
it will be clear to you
I have been a good father.
He's grown up happy
in my keeping.
So, you think it
would it be unwise
to let Endar see Jono?
I think
it might be dangerous.
Abusers can have subtle
but powerful influence
over their victims.
You see, I'm not convinced
the boy has been abused, Doctor.
I've talked with the father
and, if I'm
any judge of character
I would say that he cares deeply
for the boy's welfare.
I sense awakening memories
in the boy.
This is a very fragile time
for Jono.
If we send away the man
he calls "father"
without even letting them
see each other
how would we ever gain
his trust?
Yes.
There is something else
to keep in mind.
We are deep
in Talarian territory.
A semblance of diplomacy
is called for.
I'm going to agree
to the meeting.
All I ask is that the visit
be supervised.
Don't let them
be alone together.
Agreed.
Endar.
Jono, my son.
Have they
treated you well?
Yes, Captain.
Except...
Except what?
I was forbidden
to make the B'Nar.
Ah.
That's all right.
I know you've mourned
in your heart.
Well, Jono...
what do you think
of these humans?
They look like me.
They want to keep you, you know.
Yes, I know.
You've reached
the Age of Decision.
What is your choice?
Do you want to stay?
No.
Of course not.
Then you shall not.
I'm returning to the Q'Maire.
I will give the humans a choice.
If they do not make the one
we know is right
it may lead to war.
You may die.
I am ready to die.
WORF:
Captain, sensors
indicate
two warships
approaching
from the opposite
direction along
the border.
Mr. Data, what's
their offensive potential?
( beeping )
Talarian warships
are limited
to neutral particle weapons
high-energy X-ray lasers
and Merculite rockets.
No match for
the Enterprise, Captain.
Mm-hmm.
The last thing
I want is to
be forced
into destroying
one of their ships.
They won't back off.
They've been willing to fight
to the death in past encounters.
The lines are being drawn.
All this for a chosen son.
Captain, is it worth it
to go to war over a child?
CRUSHER:
You might not
ask that, Lieutenant
if it was your child.
There must be a way
to avoid this.
If we can just reach
Jono, help him make
some connections
with his origins
he may choose
to come with us.
Do you really think
Endar would go along with that?
If Endar respects
Talarian custom,
he may have to.
According to their tradition
a male child of 14
has reached the Age of Decision.
He then undergoes a ceremony
of initiation
after which, he has the freedom
to make his own choices.
Endar's entire claim on Jono
is based on Talarian custom.
He'd have a hard time
backing away from it now.
Captain, there is
a subspace communication
from Starfleet Command.
On screen.
Sir, the message
is for Jeremiah Rossa.
Have the boy brought
to my ready room.
Jeremiah...
my name is Connaught Rossa.
I am your father's mother.
I wish we could talk in person,
but that will have to wait.
When I heard the miracle
that you were alive
I wanted to reach out to you
as soon as possible.
I find myself wondering
what you look like.
All I can do is imagine
your father at your age.
You come from a family
that would make you proud.
Many of them
have given their lives
to bring peace to the galaxy.
You are the last of the Rossas.
I was so very thankful
when you were given back to us
to carry on the line.
Your grandfather and I
will greet you
with all the love in our hearts.
Have a safe journey home,
Jeremiah.
She wears
a Starfleet uniform.
Yes.
What is her rank?
She is an Admiral.
She outranks you?
Yes.
If I were home now,
I would go to the brae
and run along the river
as fast as I could!
Jono...
I can't do any of the things
that calm me here.
You won't let me have
my music.
You won't let me make
the B'Nar.
I feel if I stay still
much longer, I will die.
Jono...
let me show you
what I do when I
have these feelings.
Come on.
Now, you can serve
from within either
of these two sections
by bouncing the ball
and hitting it
into that top center target.
Now you have to return the ball
before it bounces twice.
All right?
Let's try it.
( phaser-like zapping )
Hmm, not bad.
I win at all the games.
I can believe it.
( indistinct shouting voices )
( blasts and explosions )
Jono?
You all right?
I'm fine.
( phaser-like zapping resumes )
( zapping continues )
( Jono grunting )
( indistinct shouting voices )
( explosions, phasers firing )
( Jeremiah crying )
MOIRA:
Jeremiah! Jeremiah!
JEREMIAH:
Mama!
No!
It's all right.
( sobbing )
She was all red.
I cried...
but she didn't answer me.
( sobbing )
She used to
sing to me.
I don't remember
the melody...
just the sound
of her voice.
( sighs )
Before I remembered these things
I was strong.
And now...
It's part of being human, Jono.
But as deeply as you feel hurt
you can also feel joy.
I do not think so.
I think I will always
feel like this.
( conversation and laughter )
How was the
racquetball?
Oh, he gave me quite a game
for his first time out.
Yes, Captain.
I'm looking forward
to next time.
I'm sure you are.
Sit down.
What would
you like?
What is that?
This is called a banana split.
It's quite possibly one of the
greatest things in the universe.
Here, try some.
That is called a spoon.
( laughing )
Forgive me.
( laughing continues )
I-I fail to understand
why this is amusing.
Access your data banks
under "humor"
subheading "slapstick."
Comedy stressing farce
and horseplay.
Ah, this, no doubt,
is a variation
on "pie in the face."
Now do you see why it's funny?
No, sir.
But I will take your word
for it.
This is very amusing.
Let's try
this again.
I'd like a fresh
banana split
and another one
for my friend here.
Right away.
( Jono chuckling )
Look at him.
He's a different person.
Who would have thought
we'd ever see him laugh
out loud like that?
Just half an hour ago,
he was crying like a baby.
( yells )
Two bleeders,
single-plane penetration.
I need the autosuture here.
WOMAN:
Yes, Doctor.
Looks like the blade hit
the sternum and was deflected.
It could have been
a lot worse.
It wasn't a dream?
I'm afraid not.
No vital organs pierced.
No major arteries.
Where's the boy now?
Worf has him in Security.
Hold still.
I want to see him.
Here, now.
He'll wait until I'm finished.
Talarian warships
converging.
Range...
500 kilometers.
On screen.
Any communication,
Lieutenant Worf?
No, sir.
We have an open channel.
Commander, the warships'
closing velocities are slowing.
Staggered approach vectors,
bearing zero
120 and 240 degrees.
Riker to La Forge.
La Forge here, sir.
The Talarians are moving
into attack posture,
classic triangular envelopment.
I've tapped the impulse engines
for additional power to shields.
We're ready, Commander.
Commander, the
Captain of the Q'Maire
requests
communication.
Here we go.
On screen.
Captain Picard,
have you made your decision?
This is Commander Riker.
What are your intentions,
Captain Endar?
Where is Captain Picard?
He has been injured.
I am in command now.
Very well.
Please prepare my son
for immediate transport.
I'm afraid
that won't be possible.
Last night,
Jono attacked Captain Picard
and tried to murder him.
We're holding him in custody.
If he had been returned to me
with the others
this would never have happened.
I hold you responsible
for this incident.
He will have to come
with us now, Endar.
It is up to Starfleet
to decide the consequences.
I do not accept that decision.
I repeat...
you will prepare my son
for immediate transport.
If he is not aboard
the Q'Maire in five minutes...
you will suffer
the consequences.
Red Alert.
( alarm sounds )
Talarian vessels
routing power to
forward rockets.
Ready all weapons,
Mr. Worf.
( hushed voices )
Jono...
why did you do it?
That does not matter.
Yes, I think it does.
It matters to me.
What matters is that I
have attacked a Captain.
I am ready to be put to death.
You think
you're going to be killed?
To attack a superior
is the worst offense.
I will die at your hands.
Jono...
you're not going to die
at my hands or anyone else's.
But I've committed
a terrible crime.
What I want to know is why?
( sighs )
You seemed so happy
just a few hours ago.
I was.
But then I thought
about my father.
I felt I had betrayed him.
I'd be throwing away
all that he'd given me--
all that I'd learned from him--
my home,
running along the river
playing in the games
sharing victory
with my brothers.
All the things
that are part of my life.
As I grew closer and closer...
to you
I knew that meant leaving more
and more of that life behind.
Forgive me, Captain
but I cannot allow myself
to do that.
The Q'Maire
is requesting
communications
on a secure channel.
On screen.
ENDAR:
Commander Riker
you have failed to transport
my son aboard the Q'Maire.
Our intentions
have not changed, Endar.
We're returning him
to Starfleet.
I regret your stubbornness.
Much will be lost.
( door opens )
PICARD:
One moment, Captain.
Captain Endar...
last night, Jono...
attacked me with a dagger.
Which he could not have done
had he been returned to me
with the others.
There was a crime committed
onboard this ship
but it was not Jono's,
it was mine.
When we found Jono
it seemed so clear
what had to be done.
We knew that if we could only
persuade him
to make the decision to stay
then you would
most likely let him.
So with the best
of intentions
we tried
to convince him
and in so doing...
we thoroughly failed
to listen to his feelings
to his needs.
That was the crime
and it has taken
a huge toll
on a strong and a very...
noble young man.
And it must be rectified.
He will return home
to the only home
he's ever known
and to the father that he loves.
To you, Endar.
Thank you, Captain.
Please transmit coordinates
for immediate transport.
Good-bye, Jono.
Good-bye, Captain.
Thank you.