BEVERLY:
Chief Medical Officer's log,
Stardate 44161.2.
We are docking
at Starbase 133
for scheduled crew rotation.
I look forward
to welcoming aboard
my mentor and dear friend,
Dr. Dalen Quaice
who will be traveling with us
to his home planet, Kenda II.
Dalen!
Oh, it's good to see
you again, Beverly.
You look wonderful.
A lie I can live with.
It's kind of your captain
to ferry me home.
It was on our way.
Thanks, O'Brien.
My pleasure, Doctor.
Dalen, I was sorry
to hear about Patricia.
She had been ill
for some time.
Is her death the reason
you're giving up
your post here?
Well, we had a
lifetime together
doing all the things
we'd ever dreamed
and more.
But when she was gone
I couldn't continue
to work in that office
sleep in that bed
without her.
The absence of her
was too distracting.
I'm not sure that I'm
making any sense.
Jack and I didn't have
a lifetime together
only a few short years,
but I understand.
When you realize
someone you love
is lost forever...
You know what
the worst part
of growing old is?
So many of the people
you've known all
your life are gone
and you realize you
didn't take the time
to appreciate them
while you still could.
Oh, I'm sorry.
There's no reason
to load all this
emotional baggage on you.
I usually travel light.
Wes, time
for the experiment is over.
I want my warp engines
back now.
I'm almost done,
Commander.
Almost isn't good enough.
You want to be the one to
explain when the captain
says "engage"
and we just sit here?
WESLEY:
I just need a couple
of more minutes.
I'm ready to try
the new warp field.
Mom?
Don't let me interrupt.
Wesley!
Right. Okay.
( whooshing )
( console beeping )
LA FORGE:
Computer, run
a level-2 diagnostic
on warp drive systems.
Antimatter containment positive.
Warp drive within
normal parameters.
Wesley, talk to me.
That shouldn't
have happened.
Why would there be
any visible phenomena
outside the warp drive?
RIKER:
Prepare for umbilical
disconnect.
Are you done?
Yeah.
Mom?
RIKER:
Clear all moorings, engineering.
Aft thrusters.
Aft thrusters, aye.
Impulse power to the helm.
( door chimes )
Dalen?
Dalen, it's Beverly.
Computer, current location
of Dr. Dalen Quaice.
There is no Dr. Dalen Quaice
aboard the Enterprise.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
( door chimes )
Come.
Lieutenant Worf,
yesterday, before
we left starbase
an old friend of
mine came onboard,
Dr. Dalen Quaice.
I requested
quarters for him.
He was assigned here.
I was not aware
of this passenger.
I'm sorry.
I thought it was
standard procedure
for you to be informed
after Captain Picard
approved passage.
It is.
Please proceed.
We were to meet
for breakfast,
but I can't seem to find
him or his belongings.
Computer, where is
Dr. Dalen Quaice?
There is no Dr. Dalen Quaice
aboard the Enterprise.
Lieutenant, Dr. Quaice
is very old
and rather frail.
If he fell somewhere
if his communicator
were damaged...
I will order a search
immediately.
Thank you.
Even if Dr. Quaice
had been injured
why would his belongings
be missing?
WORF:
Sir, I have
several teams
conducting
a deck-by-deck search.
It is not yet complete.
I have scanned
the entire ship, Captain.
Other than the Enterprise's
regular complement
I could find
no one else onboard.
Your sensors
wouldn't detect him
if he were dead.
That is correct,
Doctor.
Could, um...
your friend have returned
to the starbase
without telling you--
an emergency of some sort?
There were a lot
of people going
back and forth
between the ship
and the starbase
yesterday.
We could easily check
the transporter ID traces.
By all means,
check the trace log,
but even if the results
are negative
contact Starbase Command.
We should leave nothing
to chance.
Aye, sir.
One moment,
Doctor.
I'm sure you're aware
of the procedure
involving passengers.
Of course.
I don't know why
Lieutenant Worf wasn't
told about Dr. Quaice.
Well, I was not
informed either.
But I sent in a request
weeks ago.
Then it must have
been intercepted
before it reached me.
And someone else
sent approval?
Why?
Dr. Quaice had
been stationed
at the starbase
for some time?
Six years.
Perhaps it would be
prudent to find out
if he had acquired
any enemies there.
Course laid in
for Durenia IV, sir.
Thank you, number one.
Mr. Data?
Sir, Starbase 133
has no record at all
of a Dr. Dalen Quaice.
You said he was stationed
there for six years.
DATA:
Not according
to their computer.
I have also accessed
Starfleet records.
There is no doctor
currently serving
in Starfleet named Quaice.
In fact, I can find
no service record whatsoever.
There are no birth records
with that name.
I can find no...
BEVERLY:
Data,
I interned
with him on Delos IV.
I've known him for 15 years.
I do not doubt you, Doctor
but I have tried
173 phonetic variations
of the name, and I...
His name is Dalen Quaice.
Q-U-A-I-C-E.
Whatever your records say
they're wrong.
Mr. Worf?
We have completed
our search, Captain.
We cannot locate
Dr. Quaice.
You're not alone.
He was onboard.
I met him myself in
transporter room three.
Then it appears,
for reasons unknown
someone has taken
great pains to erase
all traces
of this man.
Who was on transporter duty
when he came aboard?
Dr. Quaice?
Was he part
of the regular crew rotation?
No, he's a friend
of Dr. Crusher's.
When did he arrive?
Yesterday at 1600 hours.
That was my watch.
I beamed this man onboard?
Yes.
I was here to meet him.
An elderly man,
not in the best of health.
I'm sorry.
I remember you being here
for a short while
but you were alone.
W-Was he invisible?
Did I carry on
a conversation with thin air?
No, Doctor.
As I recall, you came in
and you looked around
for a few moments.
I asked you if I could
help you with anything.
All you said was "thank you."
I said, "my pleasure"
or something.
And that was the end of it.
There was
no one else here.
I can't believe
that Chief O'Brien
might be lying.
Well, he believes
what he says.
And there is no trace
imprint for Dr. Quaice.
Will, I didn't
just conjure up
one of my best friends
from a test tube.
Well, if the ship's records
have been tampered with
the transporter records
could have been
changed, as well.
And with everybody coming
and going yesterday
maybe O'Brien just
doesn't remember.
Or...
Or?
It might be a good
idea to run
a diagnostic on him.
To make sure he wasn't
tampered with.
What do you think?
It's worth a try.
I'll check the replicator
activity logs.
18 hours is a long time
to go without food.
Or without
someone seeing him.
( sighs )
Chief, this examination
should only take
a few minutes.
But I feel fine.
Sit down.
Doctor, it's no use
checking my eyesight.
I didn't see your friend.
I'll be a little
more comprehensive
than that, Chief.
Dr. Crusher to Dr. Hill.
Respond, please.
Dr. Selar,
your present location?
Computer, current whereabouts
of Doctors Hill and Selar.
There is no Dr. Hill
or Dr. Selar
aboard the Enterprise.
Doctors Hill and Selar
and four other members
of my medical staff
have all vanished.
All record of their ever having
been on the Enterprise
has been excised
from the computer's memory.
Did they come onboard
with Dr. Quaice?
No, they've been onboard
for months,
but my two duty nurses
don't remember them.
Their families
don't even remember them.
As O'Brien didn't
remember Dr. Quaice.
I checked
O'Brien thoroughly.
I found no physiological
abnormalities.
WESLEY:
Crusher to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Ensign.
I'm in engineering, sir.
There's something down here
I think you'd better see.
It may be connected to
Dr. Quaice's disappearance.
On my way.
Progress, number one.
No one's seen him.
The replicator in his quarters
has not been used.
Mr. Worf, check hull
and shield integrity
for any sign
of intruders.
Yes, sir.
But I have been
closely monitoring
all onboard sensors.
There has been
no indication
that anything...
Then give me a
level-1 diagnostic
of any onboard sensors,
and run a manual sweep
of any anomalous airborne
or electromagnetic readings.
I want some answers.
I've been
experimenting
with Kosinski's
warp field equations
trying to improve
engine efficiency.
I've read your reports.
We did a test run
while we were still
at the starbase.
Here's what
the computer recorded.
WESLEY:
This is the static warp field
we created
inside the warp drive.
The experiment was
designed to see
if we could keep a
bubble like this intact.
As you'll see in a moment,
we couldn't.
There was a momentary
flash of light.
It was all over the spectrum.
I remember that.
Are you suggesting
that a bubble
could have made
Dr. Quaice disappear?
If he were caught
in it, yes, sir.
It would seem to us
like he'd disappeared.
Where would he go?
LA FORGE:
Who knows?
Could even end up outside
of our space-time continuum.
Was Dr. Quaice in engineering
during your experiment?
LA FORGE:
No, sir.
And the bubble never expanded
beyond engineering?
No, sir.
Then how could it
have trapped Dr. Quaice
or the others?
There are others missing?
Yes, and they
weren't anywhere
near engineering.
It doesn't make sense.
I doubt that a warp bubble
could alter computer records
or erase memories.
Keep at it, Ensign,
Mr. La Forge.
It's our only
working theory for now.
Has something
else happened?
Sick bay is
totally empty.
Apparently, I no longer
have any staff.
And that surprises
you, Doctor?
( scoffs )
Surprises me?
I'll say it surprises me.
There should be
at least four members
of my staff on duty
at all times.
DATA:
I am afraid ship's records
do not concur, Doctor.
What are you talking about?
You do not have a staff.
You're telling me,
I'm the sole medical officer
on a ship with over
1,000 people onboard?
DATA:
Excuse me, Doctor
but the entire ship's
complement is 230.
What?
Doctor, may I see you
in my ready room?
Would you care
for something?
So, Beverly...
Tea, Earl Grey. Hot.
You're saying that
this ship has lost
nearly 800 of
its personnel.
I know how it sounds.
None of the scans
show any anomalies.
No signs of
an intruder.
Wesley's experiment clearly
did not have the scope
to affect an entire starship.
Captain, the Enterprise
is in serious danger.
You must believe me.
I have no choice
but to believe you.
The safety of my entire crew
is at stake.
But I... I must be sure.
That I haven't lost my mind?
I just examined myself
and being the only
doctor onboard
I had to do it myself.
There were no signs
of dysfunction.
Yes, there was
an increased elevation
of adrenaline
but I think
that is understandable.
Did you find anything
that might suggest
why you're apparently
the only one among us
unaffected by this...
this phenomenon?
No.
I'll talk to Troi.
It wouldn't do any harm.
Captain, please.
Return this ship to Starbase 133
for a full diagnostic.
I realize you have my word
only to convince you.
Mr. Riker?
Captain?
Set a course for a return
to Starbase 133 immediately.
Aye, sir.
Your word has always
been good enough for me.
( electromagnetic whooshing )
( yelling )
( whooshing stops )
I've had a team in
sick bay for two hours.
We've run the
mass spectrometer
on all particulates.
We've scanned
the EM spectrum
in case there was
a wave guide
somehow leaking radiation.
We've even crawled around
in the life-support ductwork.
Captain, I don't know
what this vortex was
that Doctor Crusher saw.
I didn't just see it, I felt it.
I barely escaped from it.
Well, there's
nothing there now
and no sign there ever was.
Is there any
possible connection
with Mr. Crusher's experiment?
Could this "warp bubble"
be floating
about the ship perhaps?
No, sir, that bubble was
definitely
contained in engineering.
There's no way
it could possibly
have affected anything
up on deck 12.
Sir, I have completed level-1
computer diagnostics.
There are no malfunctions.
Have any other ships responded
to our queries, Data?
The Wellington is the only
Federation vessel
in this sector.
It reports normal operations.
A Ferengi ship
within communications range
also reports nothing unusual.
Are all the members of the crew
accounted for?
Yes, Doctor.
How many are there?
There are 114 people
on the Enterprise.
( quietly ):
What?
That is the exact number
there should be.
There are now over 900 missing.
Deck after deck
of this ship is deserted now.
How do you account
for all the empty rooms?
If there are only supposed
to be 114 people onboard
why all the extra space?
Transportation of colonists
diplomatic missions,
emergency evacuations...
Thank you, Mr. Data.
Have security confine
all non-essential personnel
to their quarters.
Computer, go
to red alert.
I'd like Lieutenant Worf
to program onboard sensors
to monitor
all personnel.
If we can catch
the moment...
I'm sorry.
Whom did you say?
Worf. Chief of security.
The big guy who never smiles?
The Klingon!
( whispers ):
Whoa.
Deanna?
I need you to tell
me if I've gone
completely mad.
If you can ask the question,
I'd say no.
Don't evade
the question.
Well, then, ask me one
I can answer.
Deanna, I've delivered
babies that no longer exist.
No one else
remembers them.
Yet I can close
my eyes and see
their faces
clearly as I
see yours now.
What if it's not
some huge conspiracy?
What if it is just me?
What if it is just you?
Then I've delayed
a mission
and frightened
a lot of people,
including myself.
So what?
You have acted
in the best interests
of your ship and crew.
What more could you ask
of yourself?
And if this turns out
to be a mistake
then we'll be a little
late arriving at Durenia IV.
That's all.
It's not a mistake.
I wish it were.
When we reach
starbase
I'll order
a complete workup
both physical and psychological.
If we reach starbase.
Wesley.
Where's Wesley?
Wesley!
Mom?
Are you all right?
No.
We may have very
little time left.
You don't believe me.
Look, mom, I don't know...
I don't have time
to convince you.
Hundreds of people
are now missing
and your experiment is the only
possible explanation we have
that we can work
on right now.
Well, there it is.
I don't know what else
to do with it.
Then find someone who does.
Someone who knows something
about... about warp bubbles.
I've already talked
to Kosinski on subspace
and he can't explain it, either.
And this is based
on his equations.
There is someone
who may be able to help
but I can't reach him.
Who?
He was
Kosinski's assistant.
He was an alien
from Tau Alpha C.
He said he was
some kind of "traveler."
somehow, he combined
warp technology
and the energy
from his own thoughts.
Yes, I remember.
Wesley, do you think
it's possible
that you've
accidentally recreated
something that he did?
Something
that could alter reality?
I don't see how.
He's the only one
who could explain it to us.
I've sent a message
to Tau Alpha C
but it's so far away,
it could take days to get there.
Maybe the captain
can help us.
We've got to find him.
Come on.
I don't even know
if he's still alive.
He was very sick.
Well, we can't stand
around here doing nothing.
It's a chance.
We have to try to...
( whispers ):
Wesley.
Wesley!
They're all gone?
Riker, Troi, Data?
Wait a minute.
Let me guess.
You never heard
of any of them.
You know, Doctor,
I have been more than fair.
I've done everything I can
to substantiate your...
... your perceptions
of a crew...
Will Riker.
Your first officer.
He's-he's very good
at playing poker,
loves to cook.
He listens to jazz music,
plays the trombone.
I cannot find
any evidence of a Will Riker...
Commander Data,
the android who sits at ops.
Dreams of being human.
Never gets the punch line
of a joke.
Doctor... we'll be arriving
at Starbase 133 in a few hours.
Deanna Troi,
your ship's counselor.
Half-Betazoid, loves chocolate.
The arrival of her mother
makes you shudder.
O'Brien, Geordi, Worf.
Wesley, my son.
They all have been
the living,
breathing heart of this crew
for over three years.
They deserve more
than to be shrugged off,
brushed aside
just pinched
out of existence like that.
They all do.
They deserve
so much more.
Beverly...
perhaps it would be best
if you were to confine yourself
to sick bay
until we arrive.
( laughing )
It's all perfectly logical
to you, isn't it?
The two of us
roaming about the galaxy
in the flagship
of the Federation.
No crew at all.
We've never needed
a crew before.
I don't suppose you remember
an alien from Tau Alpha C
who was onboard once?
He called himself a "traveler."
Jean-Luc
I don't know how,
but you and I
have got to find this traveler,
or another from his race.
If anyone
can help us...
I give you my word,
when we arrive at the starbase
I will make every effort
to find him.
It's not a delusion.
It is not a dream.
There is a physical,
measurable phenomenon
at work here.
Perhaps you could help me
to identify it.
How?
I'd like to use
the ship's computer to monitor
your life functions.
Until I disappear?
It will happen.
All right.
Computer,
continuous scan
Captain Jean-Luc
Picard, vital signs.
Audible readout.
Begin now.
Body temperature,
37.2 degrees...
I promise you,
I will continue to do
whatever I can
to find out what's happening
and to bring you all back.
Blood pressure, 122 over 76.
I'm sorry I lost my temper.
You do remember that?
Vividly.
Electrolytic balance...
But if I have forgotten
my closest friends and comrades
as you say,
then I deserved every word.
Respiration, 17.
Blood pressure...
For quite some time, I've been
meaning to say something to you.
I might not have
another chance.
Jean-Luc, you and I...
( computer readout stops )
I won't forget.
I won't forget any of you.
( electromagnetic whooshing )
( wind howling )
( yelling )
( static crackling )
LA FORGE:
Wesley, have you got it?
What's happening?
I'm losing it.
The link
isn't holding, Commander.
I'll go
to the secondary equations.
No.
Look.
I've lost it.
Damn, I'm sorry, Wesley.
It's over.
There's no way
we'll get her back now.
TRAVELER:
It's not over, Wesley.
There's still a way.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44162.5.
Two attempts to retrieve
Dr. Crusher have failed.
And now the Traveler--
a mysterious visitor
from our past-- has reappeared.
Is she alive?
As long as she
thinks she is alive
she is alive.
What the hell does that mean?
Your species have
very narrow perceptions
of time and space and thought.
When Beverly Crusher was caught
in the static
warp bubble
she created her own reality.
Her thoughts at the precise
moment she was trapped
determined its shape and form.
Can you go in and get her back?
No, it is her reality.
I cannot enter it
anymore than I can enter
her thoughts.
But you said
there's still a way.
I can help
but I can't do it myself.
Wesley...
there is a power
within each of us
that most people
haven't begun to realize.
But you have begun
or else I would not have
known to come here now.
Together, we may be able
to open a gateway for her...
but she must choose
to walk through it.
Computer, we are
going to apply
precise diagnostic methodology.
Once we've cataloged
the symptoms
we will proceed
to determine the illness
and then find the cure.
We will start
with the assumption
that I am not crazy.
If I am, it won't matter
one way or another.
Computer, read the entire
crew roster for the Enterprise.
Dr. Beverly Crusher.
Have I always been
the only member of the crew
on the starship Enterprise?
Affirmative.
If this were a bad dream,
would you tell me?
( strained beeping )
That is not a valid question.
Like hell, it's not.
What date did I report onboard?
Stardate 41154,
1400 hours, three minutes.
That sounds about right.
Computer, is there more
than one USS Enterprise?
This vessel
is the fifth starship
to bear the name USS Enterprise.
It is currently the only one
in service.
What is the primary mission
of the starship Enterprise?
To explore the galaxy.
Do I have the necessary skills
to complete that mission alone?
Negative.
Then why am I
the only crew member?
( strained beeping )
Aha, gotcha there.
That information
is not available.
Computer, are you familiar
with the inhabitants
of Tau Alpha C?
Affirmative.
Are any presently located
on any starbase or vessel
within communication distance?
Negative.
Estimated time to Tau Alpha C
at warp 9.5?
123 days.
( sighs )
Lay in a new course
for Tau Alpha C
and send a subspace message
advising them of our arrival.
Acknowledged.
Engage.
( computer silence )
Computer, did you change course?
State new destination
or coordinates.
I stated it.
Damn it.
Tau Alpha C.
There is no Tau Alpha C
listed on current star maps.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44162.8.
At the direction
of the Traveler
the Enterprise is returning
to Starbase 133
and the precise position where
the subspace bubble was formed.
Our goal will
be to create a
stable gateway
between our reality and
your mother's reality.
We've tried.
We can't stabilize the link.
Of course not.
The equations are
only the first step.
We will be going
beyond mathematics.
Just tell me
what I have to do.
Begin by letting go
of your guilt, Wesley.
It's my fault.
I shouldn't
have tried...
Focus on the present.
You will have
to be here completely
to help her back.
You must open yourself
to time and space
and the intricate threads
that bind them.
Begin entering
your warp field equations.
Now close your eyes.
See past the numbers.
Trust yourself.
( console beeping )
I can't.
I can't do it.
When the time comes,
you will, Wesley.
You will.
Starbase 133,
this is the Enterprise.
Please acknowledge.
Viewscreen on.
It's not just people.
Everything is disappearing.
Computer, what is that mist
I'm seeing?
Sensors indicate it
to be a mass-energy field
705 meters in diameter.
It surrounds the ship?
Affirmative.
If there's nothing
wrong with me...
maybe there's something wrong
with the universe.
Computer, what is beyond
the mass-energy field?
Sensors cannot penetrate
the field.
Here's a question
you shouldn't be able to answer.
Computer, what is the nature
of the universe?
The universe is
a spheroid region
705 meters in diameter.
Captain, approaching
Starbase 133.
Slow to ten meters
per second.
Mr. La Forge, prepare
for precision station keeping.
Acknowledged.
Readying thrusters.
There.
There it is.
We're moving
into phase now.
There's your warp bubble,
Wesley.
What?
What's wrong?
It is... collapsing.
Computer, give me
a graphic representation
of the universe.
I've seen this before.
Wesley's experiment.
The bubble.
Of course.
But that would mean
that I'm the one trapped
in the bubble.
( rumbling )
Computer, what's happening?
Explosive decompression,
decks 5 through 14.
Sealing off forward sections.
Cause?
A flaw in the ship's design.
Show me.
Analysis.
No ship's structures exist
forward of bulkhead 342.
Superimpose previous image
over this one
same scale,
and continue to monitor.
( rumbling )
It's collapsing!
Hull integrity
now compromised
on decks three through 15.
Computer,
how long can life-support
be maintained?
Four minutes, 17 seconds.
( rumbling )
Captain, we have
reestablished
exact coordinates
and attitude.
Geordi, we're in position.
Your status?
LA FORGE:
The warp bubble is contracting
at a rate of 15 meters
per second.
We're going to lose it
in about four minutes.
It is time,
Wesley.
( beeping )
We're ready, Commander.
RIKER:
Proceed.
I'll be in engineering.
Let it go, Wesley.
Let go
of the anticipation
the expectations
the demands
upon yourself.
Let it all go.
Leave it behind.
Yes.
The ability is there
inside of you.
You do not need
to look for it.
Three minutes, 30 seconds
to life-support failure.
The Traveler used his thoughts
to alter warp fields.
Thoughts became reality.
Now I'm in a warp field.
Could my thoughts
have changed this reality?
Come on, Beverly!
What's the next step?
What was I thinking at the
moment Wesley's bubble formed?
Dalen Quaice.
He said all the people
he'd known were gone.
I thought of Jack.
I went to see Wesley...
The flash in engineering...
That's when it started.
That's when...
I started losing everybody.
My thoughts created
this universe.
Can they get me
out of it again?
That information
is not available.
I'm not talking to you.
Click my heels together
three times
and I'm back in Kansas.
Can it be that simple?
( beeping )
( beeping quickens )
Two minutes, 30 seconds
to life-support failure.
Computer,
hypothetical situation.
A person is trapped
inside of a static warp bubble.
Determine a means of escape.
Escape would
theoretically depend
on establishing
a stable threshold
between the warp field
and the outer environment.
Describe this threshold.
Negative.
There are no known
practical applications
of this theory.
Extrapolate
from theoretical database.
How would it manifest itself?
A dynamic
atmospheric disturbance
of great intensity.
Disturbance?
The vortex.
They must have been trying
to reach me.
But how do I find it?
Wesley, where do I go?
Help me.
Stable threshold.
They've been trying to create
a stable threshold.
Where are they trying to do it?
Where did they do it
the first time?
Engineering.
One minute, 30 seconds
to life-support failure.
Engineering.
Failure in turboshaft four.
Unable to proceed
to main engineering.
Just take me anywhere
on deck 36.
( whooshing )
( whooshing continues )
( static crackling )
We're losing the bubble!
( crackling continues )
( groans )
( sighs )
Beverly?
Jean-Luc.
Oh!
You...
Do I have you to thank
for getting me back?
No.
Oh...
Jean-Luc, if I might ask,
how many people
are there onboard?
1,014...
including your guest,
Dr. Quaice.
( sighing )
Is there something wrong
with that count, Doctor?
No.
That's the exact number
there should be.
♪♪