One.
Are you trying to fill
another inside straight, Worf?
Don't say
I didn't warn you.
Pah!
I fold.
I will raise you...
three.
No cards?
The best poker face
I've ever seen.
Dealer takes two.
Your three, and...
ten more.
I will see your 10,
and raise you 20.
Data, have you got a flush
or a full house?
It will cost you 20
to make that determination, sir.
Dealer folds.
TROI:
You two have
successfully divided
the evening
between you.
I suspect conspiracy.
But far be it from me
to accuse my
superior officers.
You're getting harder
and harder to bluff, Data.
You've learned
this game very well.
Yes, sir,
I believe I have.
I'll tell you what.
I'll bet that
I can find any card
that you hide
in this deck.
And furthermore,
I will make you
help me find it.
Careful, Data.
Your guidance is much
valued, counselor.
However...
Pick a card.
Don't let me see it.
Now, lose it
in the deck.
Cut the deck into
two even piles.
Okay.
One more time.
And again.
How many cards?
11.
Take five.
Throw them away.
Pick three more.
Okay, now pick
one of those.
That your card?
Incredible.
DATA:
Not at all,
Counselor.
You surreptitiously
placed the edge
of your left thumb
against the card.
When you divided
the deck to reshuffle
you kept that card
on top.
You thus were able to have me
either save or discard
depending upon the location
of the card,
which you followed
at each step
until we were left
with just one--
the card
I originally chose.
Sir...
I believe,
under the circumstances...
Picard to Riker.
Captain?
PICARD:
We have received
a distress call.
We're changing course
to intercept.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44215.2.
The  Enterprise has bypassed
its scheduled archaeological
survey of Camus II
in response to
a distress call
from the Federation
freighter Arcos
which has assumed an emergency
orbit around Turkana IV...
birthplace of our late comrade,
Tasha Yar.
We will be entering
the Turkana system
in 11 minutes, Captain.
PICARD:
Engine status?
Stable, but we have
maintained warp factor nine
for longer than
is recommended, sir.
Subspace message
from the Arcos.
Their transmitter
is failing.
Audio only.
Let's hear it.
Enterprise,
this is Tan Tsu,
Arcos engineer.
Estimate five minutes
'til warp drive
containment breach.
( explosion )
Make that three minutes.
Thanks for trying,
Enterprise.
Ensign, warp factor 9.3.
How much time?
Seven minutes,
15 seconds
will put us within
transporter range, Captain.
9.6.
PICARD:
Mr. O'Brien,
prepare to lock
onto the two crewmen.
Aye, Captain.
DATA:
We are now entering
the Turkana system, sir.
Slow to impulse.
Visual contact,
sir.
Get them out of there,
O'Brien.
Status, O'Brien?
There's nothing to lock onto,
Commander.
I am reading
an ion trail
characteristic of a
freighter escape pod.
Unable to establish
contact.
It could have been damaged
by the explosion.
They may have been able
to maintain orbit.
Let's hope they stay clear
of the colony.
That is exactly
where the ion trail
is leading,
Commander.
Hail the colony.
I've been trying to, Captain.
No response.
They haven't been able to
maintain reliable communications
since their government
fell apart.
The last Federation
vessel to make contact
was the Potemkin
six years ago.
They were warned
that anyone
transporting down to
the colony would be killed.
Number One...
ready an away team.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are in orbit above
Turkana IV, an earth colony
that severed relations
with the Federation
nearly 15 years ago.
I'm concerned
about sending an away team,
but if we are
to discover the fate
of the two missing
Federation crewmen,
I see no alternative.
The surface settlement appears
to be all but destroyed.
Sensors show that the colonists
now live in structures
that extend nearly three
kilometers beneath the city.
RIKER:
Have you located
the escape pod's
landing point, Chief?
Yes, sir.
300 meters beyond
the colony perimeter.
Sir, we can anticipate
a violent response
to our presence.
Perhaps the doctor
should wait here
until we signal.
I appreciate your concern.
I think it's exaggerated.
Doctor, the colony
is completely lawless.
Lieutenant Yar
spoke of rape gangs and--
Mr. Worf,
I can handle myself.
She's coming.
The Arcos crewmen
may need immediate
medical attention.
Set phasers
on maximum stun.
Energize.
DATA:
The dispersion trail
continues in this direction.
The concentration gradient
definitely increases
along this vector.
The escape pod
was apparently moved
into the tunnels
ahead of us.
WOMAN:
Uh, excuse me.
RIKER:
Hardly the response
we expected.
MAN:
Pardon me.
Maybe things
have changed here.
( alarm sounding )
MAN:
Over here.
Freeze!
Identify yourselves!
We're from the Federation
starship, Enterprise.
We've tracked two of
our crewmen to this area.
Do you know anything
about them?
Possibly.
What do you mean?
They found us.
Proximity detectors.
I've seen them used
on Manu III.
Follow me!
The Alliance is holding
your men hostage,
Commander Riker,
not us.
You can expect
a ransom demand.
The Alliance?
Our good friends.
( men chuckle )
Our "good friends"
are going to be upset
when they realize
we took
their last crate
of Telluridian synthale.
Maybe I should take this
to the authorities.
We are the authorities.
The Coalition-- our cadre--
runs this side of the city.
The Alliance controls
the other side.
Take your choice.
Are you offering
to help us?
In return for some
consideration.
Phasers are in short
supply down here.
A starship isn't going
to miss a few.
That is no better
than a ransom demand.
No matter what
you give the Alliance,
they'll eventually kill
your crewmen anyway.
With our help,
at least there's a chance
you'll get your men
back alive.
All I'm asking for is help
in maintaining our defense.
We are trying
to keep the peace.
Everything we've seen
would indicate otherwise.
( chuckling )
A prank.
Our proximity implants
prevent either side
from doing
any serious damage.
They warn us when
an enemy is approaching.
WORF:
Then why do you need
more phasers?
The Alliance just discovered
a large cache of weapons.
I'm just trying
to make things even,
to preserve the peace.
You keep using
the word "peace."
We've heard
a different version
of life on Turkana IV.
Ancient history.
Where did you hear that?
A former crewman
was born here.
Where is he now?
She was killed
in the line of duty.
Well, that's as good a way
to die as any.
As I said,
ancient history.
This is now
and your men are in trouble.
We'll return
to the Enterprise
and consider
your proposal.
A gift for
your captain.
Riker to Enterprise.
Energize.
I want everything
there is to know
about the starship
Enterprise.
According to Hayne,
the Coalition and the Alliance
raid each other for supplies,
much of it non-essential.
Why?
A battle exercise.
Their defenses
apparently prevent
deep strikes into
each other's territory.
Minor skirmishes
are all that's left.
"Coalition," "Alliance."
It all sounds so reasonable,
but what you've described
is the behavior
of urban street thugs.
I certainly won't trade
weapons for crewmen.
How do you suggest
we deal with them?
We have to tell them
something.
No promises, no denials.
For now,
Hayne's Coalition
is our only safe access
to the colony.
We'll keep the door open.
See where it leads us.
Captain...
transmission coming in
from Turkana IV.
On a secure channel.
On screen.
HAYNE:
Hello, Enterprise.
Commander Riker, would you
introduce me to your captain?
I'm Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
I have someone here
you might like to meet.
This is Ishara.
Ishara Yar.
Tasha was my sister.
HAYNE:
There's an old saying,
Captain.
"The enemy of my enemy
is my friend."
I've decided it's
in my best interest
to help you get
your crewmen back.
With nothing from us
in return?
You could be forced
into paying my adversary
a ransom in weapons.
I'll do anything I can
to avoid that possibility.
What do you propose?
Ishara will be
our liaison.
I know Alliance
territory.
I can help you
with a rescue plan.
One moment.
Mute.
Reactions?
I do not trust him.
RIKER:
She could be
a fake.
We told them a member of our
crew was from the colony.
All Hayne had to do was
to search through their database
on Starfleet
to find Tasha's name.
Counselor?
He's deceiving us,
and he's clearly hoping
to manipulate us.
As for the identity
of the young woman,
I can't really tell.
Nevertheless, this is an option
we cannot neglect.
We'll continue on other fronts
as they present themselves.
For now, let's see
what she has to say.
WORF:
Open.
I have decided
to accept your proposal.
Thank you.
Good luck.
DATA:
Welcome to the
Enterprise, Ishara.
I am Commander Data.
You're not human.
I am an android.
Built for fighting?
On what do you base
that assumption?
A cybernetic device
serving on a starship.
The Enterprise
is not a ship of war.
It is a ship
of exploration.
The first thing to do is
to help you map the colony.
This is a general grid
of the tunnel system.
I can fill in the specific
details from memory.
My orders are
to escort you
to the observation
lounge.
Please come
with me.
Your sister never
spoke of you.
That's not surprising.
It is surprising
to me.
Tasha and I spent
much time together.
We had a number
of conversations.
Did she talk at all
about the colony?
Only to say that she was
lucky to have escaped.
It wasn't luck.
It was cowardice.
"Cowardice"
is a term I have
never heard applied
to Tasha.
Is something wrong?
No.
It is just that,
for a moment,
the expression
on your face
reminded me
of her.
It's been 15 years.
I don't even remember
what she looked like.
You don't believe
I'm Tasha's sister.
We have considered
the possibility.
I'm not surprised.
You can sample my DNA,
if you'd like.
Yes, I will.
PICARD:
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
Perhaps it would help
if you gave us some idea
of what we're dealing
with on Turkana IV.
The last information
describes a colony in
almost complete disarray.
It started falling apart
almost 30 years ago.
There were dozens
of factions.
They fought until the city
above ground was in ruins.
The Coalition and
the Alliance
are all
that's left?
We were the two
strongest factions.
When the government
couldn't stop the violence,
they gave us police powers.
The proximity detectors
were originally designed
by the government
to keep us
under control.
Apparently, that part of the
plan didn't work very well.
No.
After a few months...
we didn't need
the government anymore.
Tasha left you in
the middle of all that?
She didn't abandon me,
if that's what you mean.
Tasha asked me
to go with her,
but I had already joined
the Coalition.
They were my family.
Captain, we don't have
a lot of time.
Maybe we should
get started.
WORF:
Incoming transmission
from the colony, Captain.
On screen.
TAN TSU:
Enterprise...
I'm being held
by Turkana IV Alliance.
I've been instructed
to say
that you have 20 hours
to make reparations
for Federation intrusions
into this colony...
or my pilot and I...
will be killed.
Ask them if we can at least
send some medical--
( static )
Take that threat seriously,
Captain.
They'll torture them
and then they'll kill them.
My cadre has
never recovered
a hostage alive from
the Alliance.
Your crewmen could be held
in any number of places.
The Alliance
has two main headquarters
and 13 ancillary bases
of operation.
All underground,
all heavily guarded.
LA FORGE:
Captain, if I could get to
the myographic scanner...
What's that?
A sensing device
from the escape pod.
It monitors the bioelectric
signatures of the crew
in the event they get
separated from the pod.
I could install a booster
on the device
that would relay its signals
to the Enterprise.
Then we could track
the men from up here.
Unfortunately, we don't know
where the escape pod is.
Level 3-C, section 547.
We have our sources.
Access tunnels
are here and here.
We could transfer
the away team
right into
this intersection.
Don't underestimate them,
Commander.
They'll be ready
for that.
I've seen them use
this kind of strategy before.
I know it looks isolated
and easily accessible,
but my guess is
they have hundreds
on the levels above and below
just waiting for you
to make your move.
We will need
a diversion.
Transport a couple
of photon grenades
into the adjoining
chamber.
At minimum intensity,
it wouldn't kill anybody
but it would
shake them up a bit.
That won't give us
enough time.
We need to occupy them
long enough
for you
to install the relay.
Transport me into
this corridor.
My magnetic implant will
set off the defense alarms.
They'll think it's a raid
by the Coalition.
Too dangerous.
We've seen what
those tunnels look like.
You could be easily cut off
from the rest of us.
Worf...
Commander Riker,
I was ordered
to assist you
in any way possible.
That doesn't mean "as long
as it's safe or convenient."
if you had the time, we could
come up with another plan
but you don't.
Right now,
I'm your best option.
She would have
to be armed, sir.
I'd like to discuss this
with the captain.
Take Ishara down
to see Dr. Crusher.
You have Tasha's DNA on file?
CRUSHER:
The ship's
computer does.
There's always
some differentiation
between sonomic chromosomes
but not enough
to affect results.
It should take me a few hours
to run the sonomic comparison.
That wasn't too bad.
So all that's left
of my sister
is a file in a computer.
Tasha exists in our
memories as well.
How did she die?
Lieutenant Yar was
killed on Vagra II
by a malevolent entity.
In battle.
No, she was killed
as a demonstration
of the creature's power.
Without provocation.
That's not how I intend to die.
The captain approves.
You're with us.
Enterprise, we're
in position.
PICARD:
Mr. O'Brien, energize.
Aye, Captain.
( alarm sounding )
They're in level two.
Tunnel 16.
Come on.
Yosh, you're with us.
Spread out.
( groaning )
Go check five.
Yes, sir.
Check out three!
( patrols calling
to each other )
( proximity alarm beeping )
Somebody's here.
Watch your back.
I'm right behind you.
I thought it was in here.
This way.
We have movement.
Go, go, go.
Damn!
Geordi, what is
taking so long?
There's a lot
of damage here.
The myographic scanner
is operational
but the power source
keeps fluctuating.
Can you fix it?
I can probably run a shunt
from the converter.
How long will it take?
Ten minutes?
Do it.
O'Brien, lock onto Ishara.
Get her out of here.
There's a transformer substation
directly above the chamber
she just entered.
It's masking her signal.
Stand by.
Stay here and cover La Forge.
Commander...
That's an order.
Return to the ship as
soon as you're finished.
I'll signal for transport
as soon as I can.
( proximity alarm beeping )
( yells )
Get us out of here.
Energizing.
( door chimes )
Come.
How is she?
Couple of cracked ribs.
She'll be all right.
Dr. Crusher just called me
with the results
of the DNA comparison.
Ishara is Tasha's sister.
After what she did for us
down there
that doesn't surprise me
one bit.
You took some unnecessary
personal risks, Number One.
We lost Tasha on an away team
under my command.
The thought of the same thing
happening to her sister...
That's an emotional response,
Will.
We can't afford it.
Understood.
Commander.
Well done.
I've fused the bone tissue
along both fractures.
The muscles around the area
will be weak for a day or two
but you shouldn't
feel any pain.
Thank you, Doctor.
Ishara, I wanted
to thank you personally
for what you did for us
down on the colony.
It was more than I expected.
I don't run away when things
get tough, like some people.
Like my sister did.
Let me tell you
about your sister.
The first time
I saw Tasha Yar
she was making her way
through a Carnelian minefield
to reach a wounded colonist.
Her ship had responded
to their distress call,
as had mine.
When it was all over
I requested that she be assigned
to the Enterprise.
Her ship's captain
owed me a favor.
In the months
that followed
she never once failed
to put the safety of the crew
before her own
and she died doing the same.
I'm sorry
you never knew
the woman Tasha became.
I think you would have
been proud of her.
And she of you.
DATA:
What is this structure?
A main fusion source.
There's one next to each
of the Alliance headquarters.
It powers all of their
defensive systems.
This chamber is accessed
from the level below.
Entry points are evenly
spaced along this wall
every 25 meters.
Data, where was
Tasha's post?
Tactical Station--
where Lieutenant
Worf is now.
Did Tasha have
many friends here?
Yes.
She was especially close
to Commander Riker
and Lieutenant Worf
and to myself.
Are you able to have friends?
Yes.
But you don't have feelings,
do you?
Not as such.
However, even among humans
friendship is sometimes
less an emotional response
and more a sense
of familiarity.
So, you can become
used to someone.
Exactly.
As I experience certain
sensory input patterns
my mental pathways
become accustomed to them.
The input is eventually
anticipated
and even missed when absent.
Like my sister.
Yes.
Like your sister.
They've been moved
so far underground
it's been difficult
to pinpoint their signatures
but the men are here
next to one of the Alliance
headquarters.
That's about two kilometers
of solid granite
above their heads.
So much for the transporters.
Not necessarily.
We could use the ship's
phasers to cut a shaft
through the bedrock
to this storage tunnel here.
With a clear path
through the rock
we'd be able to transport
down through the tunnel.
That'll put us close enough
to get to the crewmen.
But I'll need two hours
to refit the ship's phasers
for drilling.
It's a real maze
down there.
I spent a lot of time
in that section
before they took it over.
There are blind
tunnels and dead ends
that don't even
show up on this map.
We do not have much choice.
If it wasn't for my implant
setting off all the alarms
I could guide you to your men.
We could remove the implant.
No, it has
a micro-explosive inside
that detonates
on contact with air.
When you join a cadre,
you join for life.
A small force field
containing xenon
or another inert gas
could be placed
over the incision site.
The explosive could
possibly be disarmed
at the same time
it is removed.
This is something
you're going
to have to decide
for yourself, Ishara.
Think about it
while we're waiting for Geordi.
( buzz of conversation )
Our parents were killed
in some cross fire
just after I was born.
Some people took care of us
for a few months, but then...
one day we came home
and they were gone.
So Tasha took care of me
and when I was old enough,
I joined the Coalition.
DATA:
Tasha did not.
My sister hated the cadres.
She blamed them
for our parents' death.
For everything.
No, she refused to join
and she left as soon
as she had the chance.
I always thought
she was weak for doing that.
But... maybe I was wrong.
Maybe... maybe she made
the right choice.
To work together
for something besides killing.
To be close to someone
without always having
to protect your back.
Very appealing.
You're the perfect example.
I hardly even know you, Data,
but already
I completely trust you.
I... I even consider you
a friend.
Thank you.
I would like to consider you
my friend as well.
If I had known about
this place 15 years ago
things might have
been different.
Maybe it's not too late.
Ishara is willing to have
the implant removed, sir.
Good, inform
Dr. Crusher.
She has also expressed
a desire to leave the colony.
She hopes to apply
to the academy
and eventually
join Starfleet.
Does she understand
the magnitude
of these decisions?
She claims to, Captain.
I get a sense of ambiguity
from her.
Her loyalties are clearly
divided, Captain.
Are you suggesting
we should deny her an escape
from this environment?
No, I'm just not sure
she wants to escape.
It's the only way of life
she's ever known.
Ultimately, it is her decision
to make, not ours.
Mr. Data, proceed
with the mission as planned.
Data?
Yes, Counselor?
You seem so strong
in your support.
I'm curious.
We must free the crewmen.
She appears to be
our best hope of doing so.
In addition...
I have become used to her.
Ishara.
Thank you, Data.
You are welcome.
Dr. Crusher is expecting
you in Sick Bay.
It's all so different.
To what are you referring?
On the colony, nobody does
anything for anyone else
unless they have something
to gain from it.
But I do have something
Your continued presence
on the ship.
Is something wrong?
I have to tell Hayne
and the others.
I owe it to them.
Guess I ought
to get it over with.
If you desire privacy
you may use
the Observation Lounge.
That would probably make things
a little easier.
Hmm.
Report.
It's working.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44225.3.
Dr. Crusher has
successfully removed
Ishara's magnetic implant
enabling the young woman
to guide our rescue attempt.
Without my intending it
she has virtually become
an active member of the crew.
CRUSHER:
Cardiovascular
functions normal.
Metabolism, immunity,
all other vital signs excellent.
How do you feel?
Better than I've ever felt.
Thanks for staying with me.
You might want
to keep this.
It's been with you
a long time.
( door opens, closes )
You keep it, Data.
So you won't forget me.
Have you
reconsidered
your decision
to stay with us?
No.
Just in case something
goes wrong down there.
I understand you wish
to join Starfleet.
Someday...
if I'm lucky.
On that day, it is we
who will be lucky.
Picard to Riker.
Is your away team ready?
Waiting for
your signal, sir.
Status, Mr. La Forge.
Phasers in alignment
and ready to fire.
How far must we penetrate
to safely allow
transport function?
1.6 kilometers.
Fire phasers.
Aye, sir.
1.3 kilometers.
1.4...
1.5 kilometers.
1.6 kilometers.
Deep enough for
transport, sir.
Cease fire.
Mr. O'Brien, energize.
This way.
Caution is indicated.
We're near the heart
of the Alliance.
Security is minimal here.
They aren't expecting
anybody this far in.
Ishara?
Follow me.
Are you certain?
No, I'm not.
I'm trying to remember.
I was here,
but it was a long time ago.
There've been changes.
It's through here.
ISHARA:
There.
Your men are
behind that door.
( screams )
Hold out
your hands.
( yells )
( alarm sounding )
Let's get moving!
Where is she?
Commander, look!
What the hell happened here?
She probably tried
to draw their fire.
It triggered the alarm.
Worf, get these men
back to the Enterprise.
Come on!
Data, you're with me.
DATA:
Ishara?
What are you doing?
( slowly escalating hum )
The fusion generator
is overloading.
You are attempting
to disable the defense system.
For what reason?
We have rescued
the crewmen.
I don't care about your crewmen.
We have 3,000 troops
waiting at the perimeter.
When the defenses go down,
they'll come in.
The Alliance will fall.
The Federation
will be responsible
for the resulting deaths.
I cannot allow that.
You don't have a choice.
That is not so.
I don't want to kill you, Data.
But I will.
We will both be destroyed
by the explosion.
The Coalition's been
all I've had for 15 years.
They've given me a life.
I don't mind dying for them.
But you won't have to
if you just get out of here now.
Was this your intention
from the beginning?
We never could have gotten
this deep into Alliance
territory without your help.
Our help was not deliberate.
You deceived us.
What's the difference?
You got what you came for.
Why do you care
about what we do?
Your friendship with me was part
of the deception, was it not?
You misled me
at each step
and yet,
I was completely unaware.
That doesn't matter now.
None of it does.
Now, get out of here, Data,
please!
Now!
My duty requires me
to intercede.
Ishara!
( groans )
What was she doing?
Disabling the
detection system
so her forces
could attack.
Set to kill.
Your strategy failed.
It was a calculated risk.
You gave us an opportunity
we couldn't ignore.
Ishara, are you hurt?
No.
I want her returned immediately.
You're in no position
to dictate to anybody.
She attacked
two Federation officers.
You have no
jurisdiction here.
Don't talk about legal rights.
Your jurisdiction
is based entirely
on the threat of violence.
You have your crewmen back.
Isn't that enough?
RIKER:
What do you know about...?
Commander Data, escort Ishara
to the transporter room.
Thank you, Captain.
I'm just trying to make...
Close the channel.
...to preserve the peac...
You're far more charitable
than I would have been, Captain.
I understand your
feelings, Number One.
I share them
but perhaps the fault
lies in ourselves.
We were so eager
to accept her.
Each of us
myself included,
wanted to see
something of Tasha
in this woman.
We saw more than was there.
You haven't said
one word to me.
What do you wish
to talk about?
I did what I had to do.
I'm sorry if I hurt you
in the process.
I am an android.
It is not possible
for me to be injured
in that fashion.
O'BRIEN:
Whenever you're ready.
You know, Data, I wasn't
always lying to you.
That time
we spent talking...
that was the closest thing
to friendship I've ever had.
If that means anything to you.
Energize.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Data, what's on your mind?
Recent events have
left me puzzled, sir.
It has been days
since Ishara left
and yet, my thoughts
seem to dwell on her
almost as if
I were experiencing
a feedback loop in
my mnemonic network.
I know what you mean.
It is curious that
I was so easily misled.
Make that "we."
Yes, sir.
Data, sit down.
Thank you, sir.
In all trust
there is the possibility
of betrayal.
I'm not sure
you were prepared for that.
Were you
prepared, sir?
I don't think
anybody ever is.
Hmm.
Then it is better not to trust.
Without trust, there's no
friendship, no closeness.
None of the emotional bonds
that make us who we are.
And yet you put yourself
at risk.
Every single time.
Perhaps I am fortunate, sir,
to be spared
the emotional consequences.
Perhaps.