Captain's Log,
Stardate 44246.3.
We're investigating
radiation anomalies
reported in the
Gamma Arigulon system
by the starship Lasalle.
Preliminary readings
are inconclusive.
Mr. Data?
DATA:
No changes, Commander.
I can detect
no abnormalities
in the star's
radiant energy.
Prepare two
class-1 probes.
Probes ready, Captain.
Initiate
launch sequence.
( tactical console beeping )
Captain, Klingon attack cruiser
decloaking,
bearing 010, mark 237.
PICARD:
Belay that order, Mr. Data.
Did Starfleet mention any
Klingon ships in this sector?
On screen.
WORF:
We are being hailed.
RIKER:
All stop, Mr. Crusher.
Aye, sir.
All stop.
Open a channel.
Hello, Captain Picard.
Ambassador K'Ehleyr.
This is an unexpected
pleasure.
It's good to see
you again, Captain.
Lieutenant Worf.
PICARD:
How may we be of
assistance, Ambassador?
There is an urgent matter
we must discuss, Captain.
Permission to come aboard?
PICARD:
Granted.
Lieutenant,
please receive our guest.
Captain.
I must request permission
to send another officer.
May I know your reason?
My dishonor among Klingons may
offend Ambassador K'Ehleyr.
Lieutenant, you are
a member of this crew,
and you will not
go into hiding
whenever a Klingon
vessel uncloaks.
I withdraw
my request, sir.
I just received
coordinates, sir.
Ready to transport two
from the Klingon vessel.
Two?
Yes, sir.
Energize.
( transporter activates )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( children talking )
I hope he'll be
all right.
Alexander hasn't
had much contact
with other children.
Not even a bite on the cheek
for old time's sake?
Perhaps you are not
aware of my dishonor.
I have accepted...
discommendation.
I've heard.
So, now what?
I have to perform some
ridiculous ritual
to talk to you?
You may not respect
our traditions...
but I do.
Sorry.
I just thought you
might wanna talk.
A few minutes ago,
you looked like someone
with a question to ask.
Must I ask the question?
Yes. You must.
What should
I tell Alexander?
That he has no father?
The Klingon Empire
is at a critical juncture.
We may be facing civil war.
War over what?
K'EHLEYR:
The usual excuses--
tradition, duty... honor.
DATA: The word
"excuses" implies
ulterior motives
for a conflict.
I won't bore you
with the intricacies
of Klingon politics.
Basically, two factions
are trying to seize power.
Do you believe
there is a threat
to the Federation
in this struggle?
Klingon wars seldom remain
confined to the empire.
Sooner or later, they'll drag in
the neighboring star systems,
then the Tholians, the Ferengi.
The Federation won't be able
to stay out of it for long.
This has been coming
for some time.
Only K'mpec,
the head of the council,
has been able to maintain
the peace.
Now, something
has changed that.
Correct.
K'mpec is dying.
He is aboard
the cruiser.
He has come specifically to
meet with you, Captain... alone.
K'MPEC: It's about time
you arrived, Picard.
Sit.
( breathing heavily )
( grunts )
I need your help.
If the Enterprise
medical facility
can do anything to help--
Too late.
For some months,
I have been poisoned
with small doses
of Veridium Six.
The wine.
There is no cure.
( chuckles )
What do you want of me?
After I die, you will
act in my name
to arbitrate the
struggle for power.
I will?
No one on the council
can be trusted
and... I have my reasons
for wanting
an outsider.
K'mpec, you cannot
possibly be serious.
A Federation officer
has no business--
Nonsense.
You are an
accomplished mediator.
This is no different
than any other dispute
requiring your
services.
On the contrary, I think
this is very different.
And I must
respectfully decline.
If you refuse the
dying request
of the Klingon
Supreme Commander,
it will be an insult
by the Federation
to all Klingons.
Besides, I've already
sent the order.
The leaders of
the opposing
two factions
are on their way.
You had no right to involve
me without my permission.
If I'd asked,
you would have said no.
This is not just a case
of simple mediation.
You are asking me
to choose the next leader
of the Klingon Empire.
No.
By tradition,
the two strongest challengers
fight for the right
of succession.
As mediator, only you
can designate
those challengers.
But you have just said there are
only two challengers arriving.
What is the point?
I want you
to discover
which one of them
has killed me--
Gowron or Duras.
Yes, Duras.
I thought you would
find that interesting.
Interesting.
You could say that,
since he tried to have me killed
and conspired to strip Worf
of his good name.
And... I approved.
All for the glory
of the empire.
( chuckles )
That should be
my epitaph.
Find the assassin.
A Klingon who kills without
showing his face has no honor.
He must not lead the empire.
Such a man would be
capable of anything.
Even war with
the Federation.
Very well.
I accept.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
K'mpec, who ruled
the Klingon Empire
longer than anyone in history,
is dead.
We await the arrival
of Duras and Gowron,
rivals for the leadership
of the High Council.
GIRL:
Put it on there.
( growling )
GIRL: What did you
do that for?
GIRL 2: I know, now,
we have to start all over.
BOY:
Aw, man.
There is no honor in
attacking the weak.
I would have won.
No, you must
earn victory.
Where are the
other Klingons?
There are no others
on board.
Why?
The Federation and
the Klingon Empire
were enemies
for many years.
No other Klingons
have asked
to serve in Starfleet.
Why?
A warrior does not ask
so many questions.
I don't want to
be a warrior.
Hello!
( grunts )
Well, you're back early.
He made me leave.
Maybe you should go
to your room and play.
Is he under arrest?
He knows nothing
of our ways.
Our ways?
You mean Klingon ways,
don't you?
He is Klingon!
He is also my son,
and I am half human.
He will find
his own ways.
Why the sudden concern?
You won't even acknowledge
that he's yours.
Why did you
not tell me?
And what would
you have done?
That's right.
You would have insisted
that we take the oath,
just as tradition
would demand.
You should not have
kept this from me.
Well... now, you know.
I cannot acknowledge my
relationship to the boy.
( scoffs )
It would only harm him.
Because you were
dishonored?
As my son,
he would also bear my disgrace.
As would
his children.
But why did you accept
discommendation
from the High Council?
My father was accused
of collaborating
with the Romulans at Khitomer.
I know, and I also know
that you challenged it.
Yes, at first.
Ultimately, I withdrew
my challenge.
But why, Worf?
I can't believe
you'd just give up.
What really happened?
RIKER: Lieutenant Worf,
Ambassador K'Ehleyr,
report to the bridge.
On our way,
Commander.
Klingon vessels
Vorn and Buruk
holding stations at
13 kilometers, sir.
Open a channel,
Mr. Data.
Channel is open, sir.
Vorn responding
to hail.
On screen.
Let's get this
over with, Picard.
In good time, Duras.
Even in death,
K'mpec makes foolish decisions.
You should not be
involved in this, human.
The Sonchi ceremony
will take place
in one hour
aboard K'mpec's vessel.
One hour!
What is the delay?
There is no delay.
It is the time
I have chosen.
Exactly one hour, Picard.
Do not be late.
Keep that petaQ
away from the ceremony, Picard!
He has no place
on a Klingon ship.
Picard out.
( sighs )
Contact Gowron's ship.
Tell him to meet us
aboard K'mpec's vessel.
Ambassador, meet me
in Transporter Room Six
in one hour.
We will begin the ceremony
a little late.
Mr. Worf.
Mr. Worf,
the next few days
will be difficult
for you.
You have made it clear
that I am to perform
my regular duties, sir.
I want you to know
that I am aware
of your discomfort.
Thank you, sir.
Ambassador K'Ehleyr
will be preparing me
for my role in the
Rite of Succession.
Permission to
speak freely, sir.
Granted.
Duras must not be allowed
to lead the council.
He has a legal claim, Mr. Worf.
Your personal feelings
towards him--
It is not personal, sir.
His father betrayed my people
to the Romulans.
Duras is a traitor.
Klingon tradition
may hold the son
responsible
for his father's sin.
I cannot.
Treason was his
father's crime.
Duras' crime
was to lay that blame
on your father.
I will not forget that.
But you should not forget
that you chose to accept
the consequences
of that lie.
To preserve the empire.
The issue now is whether
or not he killed K'mpec.
Sir?
He was murdered.
Poisoned.
A Klingon
would not use poison.
His murder would
have no honor.
K'mpec believed that it was
either Duras or Gowron.
Well, I know little of Gowron,
only that he is an outsider
who has often
challenged the council.
But Duras... I know him.
His heart is not Klingon.
That's Gowron.
I hope this will be brief.
It will be just
long enough to prove
that K'mpec is dead.
Qab jIH nagil.
Qab jIH... nagil.
Sonchi.
Now, complete the
Rite of Succession.
It's obvious who the
two challengers are.
We will proceed according to the
traditions and the precedents
set down in
Klingon law.
What do you know
of Klingon law...
human?
We will reconvene on
board the Enterprise--
No! Finish it here!
Now!
( explosion )
( door opens )
I have not received your report
on the explosion.
Two Klingons killed,
a few minor injuries.
Were you concerned
about me?
As head of security, it is
my duty to be concerned.
Is that it-- just official
concern for my well-being?
You know my feelings.
Maybe I've forgotten.
You were right.
I would have insisted
we take the oath.
But not just because
of tradition.
I thought about
telling you.
Wanted to tell you.
But I wasn't ready.
When I left,
you said
that you'd never be
complete without me.
It took some time, but...
I came to realize that...
I need you, too.
You're a part of me, Worf.
jIH dok.
Maj dok.
No.
I can't allow you to
suffer my humiliation.
There would be
no suffering.
I don't care what other
Klingons think of you.
But what of the boy?
He may want to live
in the empire someday.
He would be an outcast--
another traitor from
a family of traitors.
"Family of traitors."
I don't believe
that for a minute.
Respect my wishes
in this matter.
I cannot take
the oath with you.
Nor can I claim
your son.
If you cannot be
his father...
at least be his friend.
We haven't completed our
analysis of the bomb debris.
Dr. Crusher is still
studying the remains
of the men killed
in the explosion.
We need more time.
Duras and Gowron will be
here in a few minutes.
I don't think you can
delay this meeting again.
Is there any way
of stretching out
the formalities
once they arrive?
In the modern
Rite of Succession,
only a brief proclamation
that two challengers
have been chosen
is necessary.
You said "modern rite."
How was the ritual
performed in the past?
The old forms dictated
that the challengers
perform the ja'chuq.
It's a long,
involved ceremony
in which the challengers
list the battles they've won,
the prizes they've taken--
the idea being to prove
their worthiness
to lead the council.
Can the old form
still be used?
It's up to you.
You can use
whatever form you want.
Thank you.
Captain, what do you know
about Worf's discommendation?
My interest is personal.
I understand
that you were there,
that you stood by him
before the council.
I'd like to know
what happened.
I'm sorry, I can't discuss it.
Council must have
a leader now!
Complete the rite,
so I can kill this Ha'DIbaH.
You will die slowly, Duras.
You have already proved you
haven't the courage to face me.
Perhaps you should plant
another bomb.
( screams )
Mev yap!
Sit down.
We will begin the ja'chuq.
What?
This woman has been giving you
bad advice, Picard.
The ja'chuq is obsolete.
It is my choice to respect
the ancient rituals.
Each of you will have
to prove your worthiness
to lead the High Council.
That will take hours.
Or days, depending
on your cooperation.
What is this?
WORF:
A bat'leth.
It belonged
to my father.
It has been in our family
for ten generations.
Let me hold it.
No.
No, no, no.
Do not think of
it as a weapon.
Make it part of
your hand,
part of your arm.
Make it part
of you.
The next meeting
is in three hours.
I would speak with
you alone, Ambassador.
I'm honored.
Picard is prolonging
the ja'chuq. Why?
He has sufficient reason
to proceed carefully.
He relies on you
for his knowledge
of Klingon law?
Yes.
Then he values
your advice.
You could
quicken the pace.
Possibly.
Why should I?
Your position is... unique.
Have you never wondered about
serving the Klingon Empire?
I serve in my own way.
As a Federation ambassador.
A few rewards...
but little glory.
What do you want?
Command of a ship?
A seat on the council?
There are many opportunities
for you in the empire.
Opportunities that
will present themselves
only if you come to power.
You talk like a Ferengi.
K'mpec was also stubborn.
He, too, refused to listen.
Now...
he is gone.
You need not make
the same mistake.
K'mpec was old and weak.
I am not.
( chuckling )
We've completed our analysis
of the bomb debris, Commander.
The explosive was a
triceron derivative.
And the entire device
couldn't have been
more than three cubic
millimeters in size.
It could have been hidden
anywhere in that room.
There's one more thing.
The bomb had a
molecular-decay detonator.
Only one race uses
that device, sir.
The Romulans.
How could the Romulans
plant a bomb
on board a Klingon
attack cruiser?
It would be
impossible.
Not if the Romulans had help
from one of the Klingons.
Klingons and Romulans
working together?
They've been blood
enemies for 75 years.
Perhaps Duras or Gowron wishes
to improve that relationship.
A new Klingon alliance
with the Romulans?
If true,
it would represent
a fundamental shift of
power in the quadrant.
Indeed. It would
put the Federation
in a very difficult position.
Duras or Gowron?
Gowron came to me alone.
Wanted me to
speed up the ja'chuq.
Offered me a seat
on the council
if I'd help him.
That doesn't suggest a
Romulan connection.
He also implied
I'd end up like K'mpec
if I didn't cooperate.
WORF:
Captain, I disagree.
It must be Duras.
Why?
PICARD: We have had
prior dealings
with Duras that show him
to be untrustworthy.
Can you be more specific?
No.
Mr. Worf,
we have a conspiracy
on our hands
that could be a direct threat
to the security
of the Federation.
Yes, sir.
As chief security officer,
I want you to accompany me
to the next proceeding.
Captain, they will be incensed.
My presence
will be disruptive.
Yes. It will.
Computer, list stardates
of the last Enterprise mission
to the Klingon home planet.
COMPUTER:
Stardates 43685 through 43689.
How many ship's logs
during that period?
COMPUTER: 43 officer's logs,
ten personal logs.
Is there a personal log
for Lieutenant Worf?
COMPUTER:
Affirmative.
Access is restricted.
Eliminate all personal logs.
List the remaining 43
in chronological order.
We'll just take them
one at a time.
jIH Doq...
batlh!
Both your claims have been
properly made and recorded.
We are ready for the
final phase of the ja'chuq.
There will
be a recess
while I review your petitions.
I'm sure you're
as concerned as I am
about the explosion aboard
K'mpec's vessel.
I assume that you are both
continuing your investigations.
The investigations are complete.
They revealed nothing
of any importance.
Now, that's very surprising.
Our analysis
turned up some...
startling results.
Will you join us, Lieutenant?
What is this?!
He has no place here,
Picard!
I will not sit at
the same table with that.
It is my prerogative
to investigate anything
that may be relevant to
the Rite of Succession.
Lieutenant Worf is my
chief security officer.
His presence
is required.
We will not proceed.
If you wish to withdraw
from the ja'chuq...
that is your option.
Proceed, Mr. Worf.
What did your investigations
reveal about the explosion?
It was a bomb.
And was your analysis
just as...
insightful?
It was a common explosive.
WORF:
What type?
Triceron.
What about
the detonator?
DURAS:
This is pointless!
The findings were inconclusive.
Fortunately, our investigation
was more thorough.
The bomb used
a molecular-decay detonator.
What?
A Romulan device.
I will return to my
ship to confirm
these...
conclusions myself.
As will I.
Mr. Worf, please be sure
to send a complete record
of our findings to both vessels,
and to the High Council.
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
That will be all.
Computer, interlock
with the Klingon Imperial
information net.
COMPUTER:
Interlock established.
Federation Ambassador K'Ehleyr
requesting diplomatic access
to High Council record,
security code pah doQ cha.
COMPUTER:
Proceed.
Computer, display summary
of the most recent
High Council inquiry
regarding Khitomer Massacre.
COMPUTER:
Access denied.
Restricted materials,
du-ko-cha clearance only.
By whose order?
COMPUTER:
Council member Duras.
Access biographical files.
Subject name,
Counselor Duras.
Advise my counselors
on the Vorn to convene.
There is much to discuss.
Look.
What is this?
Priority message to you
from the home planet.
It seems
Ambassador K'Ehleyr
is looking into things
she should not be.
Distract the guard for me.
Yes, sir.
GUARD:
Sir... excuse me, sir.
You cannot leave your
quarters without an escort.
( door chimes )
Come.
I have been informed
of your attempt
to access restricted
council records.
I have been investigating
what happened at Khitomer.
Not at all an easy task,
considering that most
of the records are sealed.
Worf's father was a traitor.
No, the evidence was altered
to make it appear that way.
I found it interesting
to read that your father
was also at Khitomer,
and you
are the one who
sealed the records.
You dare insult
my father's name?
Don't play the wounded
Klingon for me, Duras.
You don't do it very well.
What happened in
that council chamber?
How did you get Worf to
take the blame for you?
Do not pursue
this matter further.
The son betrays his
people to the Romulans,
just as his father did...
Duras.
One of the Klingons who
died in the explosion
was with Duras,
the other was with Gowron.
I've been examining
the bodies,
trying to get a clue as to
where the bomb was hidden.
There's always a pattern
in the lacerations
and tissue damage.
It would normally give a clear
indication as to the direction,
distance, force of impact.
"Normally?"
In this case,
the pattern
was virtually
impossible to detect.
I couldn't understand it until
I looked at the dynoscans.
This wound is different
from all of the others.
It was made
from the inside out.
The bomb was implanted
in one of their forearms.
It's considered a honorable way
for a Klingon to die.
A suicide that takes
an enemy with it.
Which one of them was it?
Duras' man.
When we have more time,
I will take you
to the holodeck
and demonstrate
in more detail.
Medical emergency!
Deck eight, room 142.
( K'Ehleyr groans )
Gowron?
No.
Duras.
Alexander...
( groans )
( gasps )
K'Ehleyr.
K'Ehleyr!
( roaring )
You have never
seen death.
Then look.
And always remember.
Stay with the doctor.
Worf, when did you...?
( sighs )
Multiple stab wounds
to the chest and abdomen.
Too much trauma to the
internal organs.
There wasn't time enough
to take her into stasis.
Where's Worf?
I don't know.
He disappeared just
after I arrived.
Riker to Lieutenant Worf.
Computer, locate
Lieutenant Worf.
COMPUTER: Lieutenant Worf
is not aboard the Enterprise.
Where is he?
COMPUTER:
Lieutenant Worf transported
to the Klingon ship Vorn
at 1730 hours.
On my way.
Duras.
( Klingons muttering )
What is that doing here?
He has claimed the
Right of Vengeance.
You have no rights
here, traitor!
K'ehleyr... was my mate.
( murmurs of surprise )
( grunts )
If Lieutenant Worf
resists, sir?
He's coming back with us,
one way or another.
Set phasers
on maximum stun.
I'm the only one, Worf.
The only one who can
prove your innocence.
Kill me, and you're
a traitor forever.
Then that is how
it shall be.
RIKER:
Worf!
Mr. Worf, your service
aboard the Enterprise
has been exemplary...
until now.
Sir, I have acted
within the boundaries
of Klingon law and tradition.
The High Council
would seem to agree.
They consider the matter closed.
I don't.
Mr. Worf, the
Enterprise crew
currently includes
representatives from 13 planets.
They each have their individual
beliefs and values,
and I respect them all.
But they have all chosen
to serve Starfleet.
If anyone cannot perform
his or her duty
because of the demands
of their society,
they should resign.
Do you wish to resign?
No, sir.
I had hoped you
would not throw away
a promising career.
I understand your loss.
We all admired K'Ehleyr.
A reprimand will
appear on your record.
Dismissed.
Mr. Worf?
Isn't it time for the truth
about your father's innocence
to be told?
After all, you only
accepted this dishonor
to protect the name of Duras
and hold the empire together.
Now that he has
died in disgrace,
what is gained by
further silence?
Each member
of the Klingon High Council
has shared in that lie.
They will not be so willing
to admit their own dishonor.
But... the day will come
when my brother and I will...
convince them
to speak the truth.
My parents...
my human parents will
meet us at Starbase 73.
They will care for you.
Why can't I stay with you?
You deserve a home.
A family.
They can provide that.
I cannot.
I miss her, too.
Are you my father?
Yes.
I am your father.