Captain's Log,
Stardate 44286.5.
The Enterprise is conducting
a security survey
of the Onias Sector
near the Neutral Zone.
Despite our proximity
to Romulan territory
the mission has been quiet
and uneventful.
( playing "Misty" poorly )
( chuckling )
All right, Commander,
you've got until
your next birthday
to get that right.
Some things
improve with age.
Maybe your trombone playing
will be one of them.
It's candle time,
birthday boy.
Whoo!
All right.
So, what did you
wish for, Will?
Music lessons.
( all laughing )
Mr. Data, we must hurry
or we'll miss
Commander Riker's party.
Sir, I find it interesting
how much importance
humans place
on celebrating the day
of their birth--
a day they cannot
possibly remember.
Captain, I am detecting
some unusual fluctuations
in subspace frequencies.
We'd better take a look
at it, Mr. Data.
It appears
we are being probed, sir.
The source?
DATA:
The third planet
of the Alpha Onias system.
Our reports list it
as presently uninhabited.
Perhaps reports
were incorrect, sir.
Or maybe the rumors
of a secret Romulan base
in this sector are true.
Picard to Commander Riker.
I apologize for interrupting
your celebration
but I'm going to need
an away team.
Would you report
to the Bridge, please?
Although Alpha Onias III
is a Class-M planet
our survey teams
have listed it as
"barren and inhospitable."
Any life signs?
No, sir.
But we have traced
residual energy readings
to a cavern two kilometers
beneath the surface.
WORF:
Romulans.
It is possible.
I suppose you'll just
have to go down there
and find out.
Geordi, Worf,
you're with me.
Number One?
Happy birthday.
I'm detecting high levels
of volcanic gases--
sulfur dioxide,
methane, hydrogen sulfide.
Toxic?
Uh, we're okay for now,
but I wouldn't
want to spend
my vacation here.
What about energy readings?
Magnetic clutter
is increasing.
I cannot make an
accurate determination.
Same here, Commander.
I'm getting a lot
of confusing readings here.
( distorted ):
Picard to Riker,
please acknowledge.
Riker here.
We're having trouble
reading you.
And we're having similar
difficulties reading you.
I'm advising you
and your away team
to transport up at once.
That's good advice,
Commander.
We've got a sudden build-up
of gases here,
especially methane.
( coughs )
Transporter Room
take us up.
( alarm beeps )
I can't get
a solid lock on you, sir.
There's too much interference.
I'm trying again.
( all coughing )
Transporter Room,
what's happening?
Report!
I'm trying again, sir.
( gasping cough )
( moans )
( people talking quietly )
Dr. Crusher, he's awake.
Beverly.
Will, you remember me.
That's good.
What else do you
remember, Captain?
Captain?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Water, three Celsius.
How do you feel?
Confused.
That's understandable,
considering what's happened.
( sighs )
What has happened?
What happened
to Sick Bay?
To you... to me?
Sit down, Captain.
Captain? I am Commander
William T. Riker.
What is going on here?
Sit.
Please.
What is the last thing
that you remember clearly?
Alpha Onias III.
The Enterprise
had been probed.
Geordi, Worf and I
transported down
to track the source.
But all you found there
was toxic gas.
They barely had time
to get the three of you out.
Will, that happened
16 years ago.
That's not possible.
With an Altarian virus,
anything is possible.
In fact, we've been
expecting this.
Could you be more specific?
That day on Onias III,
you were infected
with a strain of
Altarian encephalitis--
a retrovirus that
incorporates its DNA
directly into
the cells of its host.
It can lie dormant
for many years
and then suddenly
become active again
as it did in your case
ten days ago.
You have been in a coma,
delirious.
Your fever finally
broke this morning.
But what happened to my memory?
Let me show you a scan
of your brain tissue.
When the encephalitis
became active
it caused widespread
synapse degradation
interrupting the
consolidation of
your memory patterns.
Doctor.
Will, this virus
inevitably causes
memory loss back
to the moment
of the original infection.
In your case,
all the way back
to Alpha Onias III.
I don't believe this.
Is this a dream?
Feel my hand.
It is flesh and bone.
This is not a dream.
And you are, in fact,
Captain William T. Riker
in command
of the Enterprise.
The Enterprise.
For how long?
Nine years.
If I've lost
my memory,
how do I get it back?
Memories are formed
by association.
Smells, sounds
and images
from the present
could possibly
trigger them.
Like a song reminds you
of an old friend.
Exactly.
In associational therapy
we expose the patient
to familiar surroundings.
This could stimulate the brain's
neural synapses
into regenerating.
Well, then let's get started.
There's nothing more familiar
than the Enterprise.
Maybe that'll bring back
some of my...
Will.
I said your memory could return.
In many of these cases,
the damage is permanent.
RIKER:
What about Geordi and Worf?
Were they infected, too?
Thankfully, no.
Geordi appears
to have been immune
and the Klingons don't seem
to be affected by the virus.
Speaking of Klingons.
There have been
quite a few changes
on the Enterprise during
the last 16 years.
Deck eight.
Belay that order.
We should begin
the associational
therapy in
your quarters.
Personal recollections
are always the most vivid.
My life was
on the Main Bridge.
Always has been.
If anything's going
to jog my memory...
Main Bridge.
COMPUTER:
Repeat command.
I said, Main Bridge.
The computer's been
slow all morning.
A processing
attenuator is down.
Commander La Forge has
been running a level-1
diagnostic on it to isolate the
problem.
Geordi.
Oh, it's good to see you
up and about again, sir.
Your eyes--
what happened to your VISOR?
My VISOR?
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
Dr. Crusher told us
that you might not remember.
I haven't needed a VISOR
since I got these cloned
implants, Captain.
Captain.
Welcome back, Captain.
We were not expecting
to see you
on the Bridge so soon.
Commander Data,
you are my First Officer?
Do you remember, sir?
Data, I haven't
remembered a day
for the last 16 years.
Captain, warbird uncloaking.
DATA:
On screen.
RIKER:
Shields up.
Red Alert.
Captain, we were expecting
the Decius.
There is no cause
for alarm.
Cancel Red Alert.
Clearly, I need to be briefed.
Captain, the Decius
is hailing us.
The Admiral wishes
to speak to you.
On screen.
Will.
Admiral Picard.
Deanna.
How are you feeling?
I've been better.
Not surprising,
Altarian viruses
can be a nasty business.
That's an understatement.
We'll discuss this
I can't even...
after we've transported over.
Picard out.
( murmuring )
Transporter Room Six.
How are you holding up?
I could get used to the idea
of a Ferengi ensign
but Admiral Picard
aboard a Romulan warbird?
What is that all about?
I think I should leave
all the explanations
to the Admiral.
Whenever you're
ready, Chief.
Captain Riker
it's good to see
you've recovered.
I'm not exactly sure
you'd call it
a recovery, sir.
Then there has been
some memory loss?
How much?
Everything
after Alpha Onias III.
To lose 16 years...
...it's almost beyond belief.
I have trouble
believing it myself.
It's so overwhelming to have
so much of your life missing.
And it couldn't have happened
at a worse time.
A few more days of relatively
simple negotiation
and the treaty will be signed.
What negotiations?
What treaty?
Sorry.
I'll start at the beginning...
which is four years ago.
A Romulan battle cruiser
strayed into
Federation space.
Its warp coils
had collapsed.
Life support was failing.
TROI:
You saved them, Will.
You and the Enterprise.
The Romulans
were... impressed
to say the least.
After years of distrust
and conflict
they started to talk.
You were our key spokesman
in securing the alliance
with the Romulans.
How far have
these negotiations progressed?
The preliminaries are over.
All we need do now is escort
the Romulan Ambassador
to the final session.
Where you will complete
the negotiations
and sign the treaty.
Captain...
Admiral
I am in no condition
to negotiate with the Romulans
or with anyone else.
Will, you're sound
of mind and body.
If you are properly briefed
you'll still be able
to fulfill your duty.
With a 16-year gap in my head?
We do need you.
Sir... I'm not fit
to resume command.
I appreciate your candor
but despite your condition,
there is no one better equipped
to deal with the Romulans
than you.
When do we leave?
As soon as the Ambassador
transports over from the Decius.
We will get through this...
as we have many times before.
I hope so.
Let me take you
to your quarters.
Good idea.
I've had enough surprises
for one day.
Anything familiar?
( trombone playing
"Three Blind Mice" badly )
Hi, Dad.
...and then Mr. Greenburg
asked about the Fornax Disaster
and I knew the Enterprise
saved all the colonists
but I didn't know...
Ah, here it is.
But I didn't know
the exact stardate
of when their sun went nova.
So if you tell it to me,
I'll write it down
and that way
I won't forget.
You don't remember me, do you?
I'm sorry.
TROI:
I need to talk to
your father, Jean-Luc.
Would you mind
leaving us alone
just for a moment?
Why didn't you warn me?
Beverly hoped that
meeting him like this
might make an impact--
help you remember.
Well, it made an impact,
all right.
Give it time.
Jean-Luc.
Yes.
The Admiral was very pleased
when you chose that name.
He's a wonderful boy.
Deanna...
who's his mother?
She died two years ago.
A shuttle accident.
I'm sorry, Will.
I have no recollection
of her at all.
What was she like?
Min was beautiful
of course.
Strong,
intelligent, patient.
Well, she was married to me.
She had to be patient.
She was
an excellent Captain's wife
and a very good
ship's counselor.
She took over after I left.
I can't imagine
you leaving the Enterprise.
Admiral Picard
offered me a position
at Starfleet Command.
It was a tremendous opportunity.
I couldn't refuse.
But what's important
right now,
today
is that you have a son
who needs you.
Spend time with him.
You may find part
of what you've lost.
( door opens, closes )
( trombone playing
off-key scale )
Pretty bad, huh?
I've heard better.
I've been practicing
but I...
I still
can't get a good tone.
You're putting too much
pressure on the mouthpiece.
Relax the embouchure.
Don't use any muscles
you don't need.
Show me again.
Left hand, right hand.
( playing scale )
( playing "Misty" )
( plays flat note )
( chuckles )
16 years, you'd think
I'd be able to hit that note.
Come on, Dad.
You always make
that mistake.
Computer, summarize
service record
Riker, William T., Captain.
Begin with the Fornax Disaster.
Please restate question.
Service record,
Riker, William T.
( strained beeping )
Damn it.
Dad?
Computer lag.
I can't believe Geordi's
still running his diagnostic.
Is, um, that
what you wanted?
Picard to Captain Riker.
The Romulan Ambassador
is ready to transport
over from the Decius.
On my way.
I've got to go.
Sure.
Dad?
Everything's going to be fine.
Thanks.
Bye.
Troi tells me
you met Jean-Luc.
How is my namesake
holding up to all this?
Better than I am.
We did our best
to prepare him.
I'm trying to catch up
with all this.
I've still got
a long way to go--
a long way.
Just follow my lead
with the Ambassador.
You'll be fine.
The Decius reports
the Ambassador is
waiting to transport.
Beam him aboard.
Admiral Picard,
Captain Riker.
It's good
to see you again.
Ambassador Tomalak
welcome aboard
the Enterprise.
Thank you, Admiral.
It is an honor
to be the first Romulan
to freely walk
about a Federation starship.
Ambassador Tomalak?
At Nelvana III,
he threatened
to take the hull
of the Enterprise home
as a war trophy.
That was a long time ago.
Many things have changed,
including Tomalak.
TOMALAK:
As soon as we arrive
at your Outpost 23
the final negotiations
should go quickly.
I agree, Ambassador.
All of the difficult issues
have been resolved.
After much debate.
Your Captain Riker
is the kind of negotiator
even the Ferengi
should avoid.
But we have come
to an agreement
both sides
are happy with.
Largely thanks
to Captain Riker.
And we are grateful,
Captain.
The new alliance
will greatly benefit my people.
As I hope it will
benefit mine.
Oh, it will,
Captain, it will.
Main Bridge.
The virus you
contracted, Captain--
have you fully recovered?
I assure you, Captain
Riker is quite well.
He is looking
forward to attending
the final negotiations as
planned.
Excellent.
The signing of this treaty
is an historic occasion.
You, of all people,
deserve to be there.
Thank you... Ambassador.
So this is the Bridge
of the Enterprise.
And this, I assume
is your tactical position?
Impressive.
RIKER:
Excuse me.
Admiral, Deanna
I need a moment
with you.
Commander Data,
if you would
accompany the Ambassador
on his... tour?
Certainly, sir.
Excuse us, Ambassador.
Ambassador, you may find
this of interest.
These newly
refined sensors
are capable of pinpointing
power emissions
of a cloaked warbird
even at warp.
You say you trust Tomalak?
I trust the process
we have built
with the Romulans
over the past four years.
They have nothing
to gain by betrayal.
Are you sure?
You've always said it's
a chess game with the Romulans--
move, countermove,
guile and deceit.
I sense no such dishonesty
in Tomalak.
His desire for peace
is sincere.
He wants this alliance.
There's no cause
for concern.
No cause for concern?
We're talking about revealing
the location of Outpost 23--
the key to all of our defenses
in the Neutral Zone.
I'm sorry, Will.
Your information is out of date.
The strategic importance
of Outpost 23 is minimal.
Has been for years.
Dr. Crusher to Riker.
Are you there, Captain?
What is it, Doctor?
Your son has been injured.
He's been taken to Sick Bay.
You'd better come down here
right away.
Dad.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
What happened?
It's broken
but it's going to be all
right in just a minute.
Now, let's go easy
on this arm
for a little while, okay?
How did this happen?
I was in the gym...
playing parrises squares.
Parrises squares?
I fell off the ramp.
At your age, you could
break your neck!
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
Continue the
compression attenuator
for another two minutes.
Yes, Doctor.
Can I talk to you
for a moment?
I'll be right back.
Will, how old were you
when you first started
playing parrises squares?
All right. I was probably
a little younger than he is.
It's just that, for
all practical purposes
this is my first day
as a father
and he almost kills himself.
He didn't almost
kill himself.
He just broke his wrist.
Just like a lot
of other boys his age
when they fall.
You're right.
It's difficult.
Difficult for you.
What about for Jean-Luc?
Can you imagine
how he feels?
You've lost 16 years.
Jean-Luc has lost
a lot more than that.
First, his mother...
and now, his father.
Good as new, Captain.
You can take
him home.
Thanks.
How's the arm?
It's fine.
Dad, I'm really sorry.
I mean, I know you have
more important
things to do...
There is nothing more
important than this, son.
Captain.
Deck eight.
Halt.
I know how hard
this is for you.
It's okay, Dad.
No, okay is not
good enough.
When I was your age
my own father
wasn't there for me
and I really needed him.
I've often wondered
what kind of father I'd be.
I never felt quite ready.
The idea even scared me
a little.
Scared?
You?
Yeah.
But I guess I got over it--
you're here.
Resume.
It's important to me
that I don't
let you down, Jean-Luc.
You never have, Dad.
You've always
been there for me.
I'll have to take
your word for that
because I don't
remember any of it--
your first step,
your first tooth, nothing.
And I want to remember.
I guess there's
only one thing we can do.
We've got to build
some new memories.
( door opens )
I'm not sure it's still
in the memory banks
but I used to have
a great fishing program
on the holodeck.
The Curtis Creek program?
You know it.
Sure, we've gone
to Curtis Creek
lots of times.
Would you like
to go again?
You bet.
Well, as soon as
these negotiations
are out of the way
you and I are
going fishing.
Great.
...and then Mom tried
to net the fish
and she fell
in the creek, too.
And then you tried
to pull us both out
and you fell in.
I'm not sure
I want to remember that.
Mom really liked
Curtis Creek.
We went there
for picnics
and stuff lots of times.
What was she like?
She was great.
I think of her a lot.
I better go change.
Computer...
display family record,
Riker, William T.
Limit to visual.
Display family record,
Riker, Mrs. William T.
( strained beeping )
Please restate request.
RIKER:
Damn!
What's wrong, Dad?
The computer still
isn't working properly.
I can't bring up a
visual of your mother.
But I know Mom's pictures
are in there.
Did you give a stardate?
Computer
display family record,
Riker, Mrs. William T.
Home file,
Stardate 58416.
Min.
Minuet.
Mom was beautiful,
wasn't she?
Yes.
( console beeping )
What's wrong, Dad?
La Forge to Riker.
Riker here.
Captain, please come
to the Bridge.
On my way.
What's the problem?
I've had to shut down
the warp engines, Captain.
Why?
Antimatter containment
fields are fluctuating.
It's nothing to worry
about though.
We're on the edge
of the Neutral Zone
at impulse power,
and you're not concerned?
I'll have the engines
back on line in no time.
Like you tracked
down that faulty
processing accelerator?
I'm running
a level-1 diagnostic.
For 30 hours?
It would never
take you more than four.
You're incapable of that level
of incompetence, Mr. La Forge.
Worf, where did you get
that scar?
In combat.
What battle?
When?
Which sector?
Which unit?
Mr. Data, if we
left immediately
when would we arrive
at Outpost 23?
At warp one
three days, four hours...
What about
at warp seven?
At warp eight?
At warp nine?
What's the matter, Data?
What happened to
those millions
of calculations
per second?
Pardon me, sir.
I am experiencing
subspace interference
which limits my abilities.
I can't operate as quickly as...
What did you say?
I said I cannot operate...
No, that's not what you said.
You said, "I can't."
You used a contraction,
didn't you?
Sir, I can explain
if you would just give me...
No, you can't.
Don't even try.
Captain, perhaps
it would be best
if we
discussed this...
Shut up!
I beg your pardon?
I said shut up
as in close your mouth
and stop talking.
Will, I sense
how upset you are.
You're angry
and impatient...
Deanna, back off.
Well, would anyone else
like to speak up
or shall we end this charade?
As you wish, Commander Riker.
The charade is over.
The Enterprise, my son--
you created it all.
With the help
of our neural scanners
and what you would
call a holodeck.
Now, please tell me.
How did you discover
the truth?
The future
we created for you
should have been
convincing.
It wasn't.
There was a computer
time lag, for one thing.
Unavoidable.
Our scanners have
a limited response time
so whenever you strayed
from our... expectations...
But surely, that was
not enough to...
To smash your
house of cards?
No, it was
the visual record
of my "wife," Minuet.
Bad move.
But we chose someone from
your past who is still alive
a woman you were
extremely attracted to.
Your mistake, Tomalak.
Minuet was nothing more than
a computer-generated fantasy
I once experienced
on another holodeck.
Impossible.
In your mind, that woman
exists physically.
Your feelings toward her
remain quite passionate.
She was part of a
very special program.
( sighs )
So much effort,
so little accomplished.
If it was Outpost 23
you were after
why didn't you use
your neural scanners
to probe my mind?
Our scanners
are calibrated
for Romulan
brain patterns.
When it comes to human brains,
they are less efficient.
There were gaps
in the information
we gathered
from your memory.
Gaps?
From what I saw, I find
that hard to believe.
You recreated
the Enterprise--
the crew,
every nuance,
smell, sound--
with perfect accuracy.
I didn't see any gaps.
I don't buy it, Tomalak.
We are wasting time.
Bring him!
( door opens )
When you and your colleagues
transported to this planet
you were less than
a kilometer from this base.
Your capture was
a simple matter.
My colleagues,
where are they?
We allowed them to
transport safely back
to the Enterprise
but your signal
was diverted.
They won't stop
looking for me, Tomalak.
They already have.
Please, say hello to your son.
Jean-Luc?
That is not his name,
of course
nor have you ever
really met him.
We merely used his image
to augment your program.
What have you
done to him?
While I am gone,
please give
careful thought
to your situation.
What's your name?
Whoa!
If we're going
to get out of here
you're going to have
to trust me.
Easy. I'm not
going to hurt you.
Who are you?
How did you get here?
My name is Will.
Ethan.
They brought me here
with my parents.
We were at a research
station at Miridian VI.
Miridian VI?
On the edge
of the Neutral Zone.
I thought
that was uninhabited.
The station was
set up last year.
Then the Romulans came.
It's odd that
the Enterprise
wasn't advised.
Where are
your parents now?
They took them away.
Do you know why the Romulans
are keeping you here?
No.
I just want to get away.
I'll get us
out of here, Ethan.
How?
Even if we
do get away
they'll find us.
They found me
when I escaped before.
You escaped?
Yes.
I hid in a secret place
for weeks.
They caught me when
I came out to find food.
I want that information,
Commander.
I want the location
of Outpost 23.
Very well, I have
been given permission
to use whatever means
are necessary.
Ethan, no!
Stop him!
( grunts )
That secret
hiding place of yours?
This way!
In here!
( scanner beeping )
Their sensors
should have picked us up.
No, they can't.
I heard them.
There's something
in these rocks.
Heavy metals?
Right.
The Romulans forgot
all about this storeroom
when they rebuilt their tunnels.
Here, we can use these.
Help me.
After I escaped
last time
I mapped out
all their tunnels.
Supply depot.
Mm-hmm.
Communications
living quarters
and shuttle bay.
How many guards
in the shuttle bay?
Only two or three.
If we stole a shuttlecraft,
that would get us nowhere
because the Romulans
could follow their own ship
too easily.
But if we broke into
their communications system
we could send a message
to the Enterprise.
Can't do that.
The transmitter
is on a voice-activated
security system only.
Do you know whose voice
activates it?
Only Ambassador Tomalak.
Who?
Tomalak.
Ambassador Tomalak?
Tomalak is a Romulan Captain.
The only time
he was ever called Ambassador
was in a holodeck fantasy.
How do you
know about that?
You, uh... you
told me about him.
Who are you?
What is your part
in all this?
( clattering, distant voices )
They've found us!
But you said the sensors
didn't work in these tunnels.
Uh, they must
have fixed them.
We've got to go.
Where are we going
to go, Ethan?
The shuttle bay.
There's still time.
No, I've had enough.
Commander, surrender
your weapon.
No more games.
No more fantasies.
I'm not going to play anymore.
It was never the Romulans.
It was you all along, wasn't it?
There is no question
about it, sir.
It is his signal.
Picard to Commander Riker,
do you read me?
Riker to Picard, I'm here.
Are you all right?
Yes, sir, I'm all right.
What about Geordi and Worf?
We beamed them up an hour ago.
They're fine.
But we lost you
in mid-transport.
Where have you been?
What is going on down there?
I'm not sure yet, sir.
But I think I'm
about to find out.
Stand by.
What shall I call you?
Ethan? Jean-Luc?
Doesn't matter.
This room, it's more
than a holodeck, isn't it?
Much more.
The neural scanners
read my mind.
Give me anything I want--
just like they tried
to give you everything
you wanted.
Everything I wanted?!
You probed the Enterprise.
You lured us here so you
could play games with me.
I didn't want
that, you did.
Why?
My world was invaded.
My people, killed.
My mother brought me here
so our enemies
would never find me.
They found her, didn't they?
She knew that they
would never stop
looking for her...
so she made sure
I would be safe.
( whirring pulses )
She left the scanners
to protect me--
to give me
anything I wanted.
Anything?
Then why did you kidnap me?
I wanted you to stay.
It's been so long.
I just wanted somebody... real.
I thought that you'd be happy.
I'm sorry.
I have to return to my ship.
Come with me.
You don't have to stay
here anymore.
You don't have
to be alone anymore.
My name is Barash.
To me, you'll
always be Jean-Luc.
Two to transport.
♪♪