DATA:
Second Officer's Personal Log,
Stardate 44390.1.
Record entry for transmission
to Commander Bruce Maddox
Cybernetics Division,
Daystrom Institute.
Dear Commander Maddox
in reference
to your most recent letter
I agree that your study lacks
sufficient primary source
information on my programming
and operation.
Therefore, in response to your
request, this correspondence
will include a complete record
of my activities
during a normal day
with particular emphasis on
my perceptions of friendship.
Commander Riker,
you are 15 minutes early.
Well, it's a very special day.
I thought the father
of the bride would enjoy
being relieved early
on the wedding day.
Thank you, sir.
Nervous?
I cannot become nervous, sir.
However, I do sense
a certain... anticipation
regarding my role
in the wedding.
Anything to report?
All systems are normal, sir.
Sick Bay reports
that Lieutenant Juarez
went into labor at 0400.
We remain at station
awaiting the arrival
of Starship Zhukov
and guest quarters
have been prepared
for Ambassador T'Pel.
Thank you.
I have the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
Begin day watch.
DATA:
Initially, Commander Maddox
I found it difficult
to maintain friendships
since human emotions
are often puzzling to me.
Eventually,
I developed a program
enabling me to predict
human emotional responses
to specific actions.
( door chimes )
Come in.
It is time for the
wedding rehearsal.
I know.
Data, I've decided
not to go through with it.
You do not wish to rehearse?
No, I'm calling off the wedding.
May I ask why?
It's just the right thing to do.
Have your feelings
for Chief O'Brien changed?
I'm supposed
to be getting married, Data.
I should be happy, but I'm not.
I just feel this weight
pressing down on me.
Will canceling the wedding
make you happy?
Yes.
He'll probably
be just as relieved as I am.
Data
you introduced us to each other.
You mean a lot to both of us.
I would really appreciate it
if you would talk to Miles
for me.
If you wish.
My friend Chief O'Brien
often says
that above all else,
he wants to make Keiko happy.
Since canceling the wedding
will make her happy
I must conclude the Chief will
be pleased at her decision.
I have good news.
Oh?
Keiko has made a decision
designed to increase
her happiness.
She has canceled the wedding.
She what?
Canceled the wedding?!
Today?
Without even a word?
Of all the childish, selfish,
irresponsible things to do!
Next time, maybe I should
deliver the good news.
Commander Maddox,
it would appear that my
program
designed to predict emotional
responses needs... adjustment.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
DATA:
Second Officer's Personal Log,
supplemental.
This is the 1,550th day
since the Enterprise
was commissioned.
Besides the arrival
of Ambassador T'Pel
other events occurring today
include four birthdays,
two personal transfers
a celebration
of the Hindu Festival of
Lights
two chess tournaments,
one secondary school play
and four promotions.
Overall, an ordinary day.
The Zhukov is ready
for transport, sir.
Energize.
Welcome aboard the Enterprise,
Ambassador.
I would meet
with your Captain.
Since I am not affected
by emotional considerations
I am closer to being Vulcan
than human.
However, while their devotion
to logic
does have a certain appeal
I find their stark philosophy
to be somewhat... limited.
( door chimes )
Come.
Ambassador T'Pel.
I come to serve.
Your service honors us.
This is my First Officer,
Commander William Riker.
Leave us, please.
Charming woman.
The tone
of Commander Riker's voice
makes me suspect
that he is not serious
about finding
Ambassador T'Pel charming.
My experience suggests
that, in fact, he may mean
the exact opposite
of what he says.
Irony is a form of expression
I have not yet
been able to master.
You don't need
a haircut.
You were just
in here last week.
Hey, if you'd done it
right the first time
I wouldn't need to be
back here so soon.
( chuckles ):
I know you want
to look beautiful
but I'm just a barber,
not a miracle worker.
Just try to keep my ears
on straight today, all right?
Friendly insults and jibes--
another form of human speech
that I am attempting to
master.
In this case, with the help
of Commander Geordi La Forge.
Hi, Data.
I consider Geordi
to be my best friend.
Here for a trim?
My hair does not require
trimming, you lunkhead.
What?
My hair does not require
trimming...
Lunkhead?
I am experimenting
with friendly jibes and insults.
It was not meant
as a serious disparagement.
( chuckles )
Well... just don't try it
on the Captain.
No.
Geordi, I am still confused
by Chief O'Brien's reaction
this morning.
Mm, yeah.
He was just surprised, Data.
He didn't mean
to blow up like that.
He knows that Keiko
probably doesn't want
to call off the marriage.
She's just getting cold feet.
( instrument humming )
Cold feet?
Jitters.
A nervous reaction
to an impending event
of great importance.
Right.
Don't worry.
Everything's
going to be fine.
She'll change her mind again.
She will?
Absolutely.
So, you believe that
the marriage will still proceed?
Trust me.
They're going to get married,
so you'd better find a gift.
I find Lieutenant Worf
to be what is called
a kindred spirit.
We were both orphans
rescued by Starfleet officers.
In many ways, we are both still
outsiders in human society.
Are you here
to find a wedding gift?
Yes.
I would appreciate
your help in selecting
an appropriate item.
Of course.
I have attended human
weddings before.
WORF:
Hold.
DATA:
This is a
traditional gift?
Yes, my adoptive parents
often give these... things
at family weddings.
A human custom.
WORF:
Hold.
It is my understanding
that the item selected
should reflect the personality
of whoever is giving it.
This does not
remind me of you.
Have you ever been
an actual participant
in a human wedding?
No.
You would not consider it
to be an honor?
An honor, perhaps
but human
bonding rituals
often involve a
great deal of talking
and dancing and...
crying.
Dancing?
I am rarely in need
of Dr. Beverly Crusher's
professional services
as my biomechanical
maintenance program
is self-sufficient
but I often observe as she
practices medicine on others
and have learned a great deal
about human interaction
from her.
Doctor, may I ask
a favor of you?
Of course, Data.
Would you teach
me to dance?
What?!
I would like to learn
how to dance.
Why me?
It was in your service record--
"Awarded first prize, tap and
jazz competition, St. Louis..."
Okay, okay.
Have I said something
to upset you?
It's just that... that
was a long time ago
and I don't want to be known
as "The Dancing Doctor..."
again.
Then your answer is no.
All right, but...
let's keep this
between you and me.
Of course, Doctor.
PICARD:
Commander Data,
please report to the Bridge.
Acknowledged.
( door opens )
Data, I want a tactical
projection of possible
Romulan deployments
along the Neutral Zone.
Access all Federation
records on the subject
and report
to my ready room.
Captain, is there a specific
area you wish me to study?
No.
Ambassador.
Number One, set a course
130 mark 246, warp seven.
That will take us very close
to the Neutral Zone, Captain.
I'm aware of
that, Number One.
Proceed.
Lay in the course.
It is fortunate that I am
able to perform my duties
without emotional distractions.
If that were not the case
a sudden course correction
toward the Neutral Zone
would make me very...
nervous.
Mr. Data, based
on your analysis
what is the current
Romulan strategy
behind the deployment
of their ships in this sector?
Their ships are deployed
to support a policy of
confrontation designed to test
Federation defenses
along the Neutral Zone.
Do you predict any change
in the near future?
I predict a 90% probability
that they will continue
to support that policy.
And is there any indication
of a more conciliatory attitude
on their part?
No, sir.
Caution is clearly called for,
Captain.
However, the mission
must proceed as planned.
Starfleet Command
agrees with you
but I would feel better if you
would consent to an escort
or a...
Thank you, Mr. Data.
Feline supplement... 74.
( meowing )
( beeping )
( meows )
Computer,
run fluidic sensor diagnostic.
COMPUTER:
Diagnostic complete.
All systems functioning
within normal parameters.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Am I intruding,
Commander?
No.
Would you care to sit down?
When one of my friends
is distraught, I have learned
that the thoughtful thing to do
is to attempt to make him
feel more comfortable.
May I offer you some
refreshment, Chief?
No, thank you, sir.
First of all,
I'd like to apologize
for this morning in Ten-Forward.
There is no need to apologize.
I was not offended.
Would you like a pillow
or a more comfortable
chair to sit upon?
No, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Perhaps you would
like some music?
Brahms? Aurelia?
No, really, sir, I'm fine.
I came to ask for your help.
It's about Keiko.
I'd like you to talk to her--
convince her to go through
with the wedding.
Would Counselor Troi not be
a more appropriate choice
to speak with Keiko?
She already has.
Didn't help.
You've known her longer
than I have.
I just thought
she might listen to you.
She won't even talk to me.
I do not know
what to say to her.
Just talk with her--
make her see reason.
She's going off half-cocked,
not thinking this through.
You've worked with her
for a long time.
She respects your opinion.
Perhaps...
Perhaps she has not
fully analyzed her decision.
I will try.
Thank you, sir.
I won't forget this.
Commander Maddox,
I noted that Keiko
was quite calm and rational
when she informed me
of her decision this morning.
Therefore, I can predict
that she will respond
to an objective analysis
of the situation
based on the available facts.
It is fortunate
that she has not
let emotional considerations
cloud her judgment.
It should make my task
much simpler.
What?
I believe you have made
an incorrect analysis
of the facts at hand.
What do you mean?
You do not seem happy.
Well...
Your decision was based
on the assumption
that canceling the wedding
would make you happy.
This has proven
to be incorrect.
Data, it's not that simple.
Since your actions
did not produce
the desired result
the only advisable solution
would be to reexamine
your decision-making process
and look for errors.
I knew what I was doing.
It's my decision.
That fact is not in dispute.
However, you may have
acted with undue haste
and in doing so,
unintentionally hurt
Chief O'Brien's feelings.
I did what I had to!
Why are you doing this?
I thought you
were my friend.
I am your friend.
Then leave me alone.
If I have offended...
Just leave me alone!
It is clear
that I need guidance
to resolve this situation.
Counselor Troi's advice
should be useful.
In many ways, Deanna Troi
is the friend
I understand the least.
Her life and her duties
are predicated
on her understanding
and perception of emotions.
Since I have none,
no doubt she finds me
as much a mystery
as I find her.
Chief O'Brien
talks to me.
Keiko talks to you.
Why do they not talk
to each other?
That's a good question, Data.
I wish I had
a good answer for you.
Perhaps, when they're ready,
they will.
Hmm.
Many aspects of this situation
are puzzling to me.
I have been studying
various texts
on the subject of marriage
but I have not found
a suitable guide.
A suitable guide for what?
In an effort to be helpful,
I am attempting to calculate
the variables involved
in a successful marriage.
Good luck.
There are
many opinions.
On Galvin V, a marriage
is considered successful
only if children are produced
within a year of the marriage.
Andorian marriages require
groups of four, unless...
Data, would you like my advice
on how to help them?
Don't.
This is something they have
to work out for themselves.
But... I am their friend.
Should I not stand with them
in a time of difficulty?
There are many ways
to help a friend
and sometimes the best way
is to leave them alone.
Do you believe it
to be the correct decision
for them to marry?
I don't know.
They're very much in love,
but sometimes that isn't enough.
Marriage is an agreement
to share who you are
with someone else
to spend your lives together,
to grow old together.
"To grow old together"?
That is an integral component
of marriage?
Usually.
Why do you ask?
Although I am an android
I have not excluded
the possibility
that I, too, may someday marry.
Data, I had no idea
you'd thought
about getting married.
I believe I have much
to offer a potential mate
however, we cannot
grow old together because...
I will not grow old.
Data...
you do have
a lot to offer.
Commander Data,
this is Ambassador T'Pel.
Please report to my quarters.
Acknowledged.
( door chimes )
Enter.
You have
priority three clearance
aboard the Enterprise?
That is correct,
Ambassador.
I require information
on the ship's defense
and navigational systems.
Access code kappa alpha 4601704.
The code is valid.
What is the field strength
of this ship's deflector shields
at maximum output?
May I ask the purpose
of your request?
I require
this information.
I have the same
safeguards
as the ship's computer.
Therefore, I must
report any inquiry
regarding restricted
information
to the Captain.
Your reaction suggests
you do not wish the Captain
to be informed of your inquiry.
I was not interested
in the information.
I was curious
as to your security safeguards.
They appear to be adequate.
Cancel the request.
You may leave.
Commander Maddox, I have
often wished for the sense
that humans
call intuition or instinct.
Since Vulcans
are incapable of lying
I must accept the Ambassador's
explanation as the truth
but I would still prefer
a "gut feeling"
to back up this conclusion.
COMPUTER:
Program Crusher four
in progress.
Hi, Data.
( shoes tapping )
Well, what do you think?
It is a re-creation
of the studio
I had my first
dance lesson in.
It appears to be
quite suitable, Doctor.
Let's start
with something simple.
Stomp... hop.
Try it.
( shoes tapping )
Again.
Good.
Good!
Am I dancing, Doctor?
Not quite.
Stop, Data.
Now try this.
Doctor, perhaps
it would be beneficial
to teach me the final lesson.
Okay.
( complicated tap rhythm )
That's great.
Watch.
Good.
Triples.
Watch.
Stop, Data.
And you say you've
never done this before?
Try this.
( rapid tap rhythm )
Stop, Data!
Not bad.
Yeah, not bad.
Then I have successfully
learned to dance?
I'd say you've
picked up the basics.
Thank you, Doctor.
I am now prepared
to dance at the wedding.
Wedding?
Keiko's wedding.
Data, you never told me
this was for the wedding.
Is that important?
Well, yes.
They don't do a lot
of tap dancing at weddings.
Why?
Well, Data, because...
I don't really
know why, Data.
Look, why don't I
just teach you
a style of dancing
that they will do
at the wedding.
Computer, run...
"Isn't It Romantic?"
( music starts )
Now, compared
to what we've just done
this will be simple.
Just look up
and follow me.
One, two, ready and...
No, Data, wait a minute.
Ow! No, no, you're just
moving... move slowly.
Ow! Ow!
Stop music!
Sorry, Doctor.
I don't understand, Data.
You picked up
the tap dancing so quickly.
I cannot reproduce
your performance
if I cannot
see your feet.
All right.
Well, let's try it again
and this time,
watch my feet.
Computer, start music.
( music starts )
And...
Now, don't just imitate me.
You've got to lead.
Lead where, Doctor?
Well, indicate to your partner
where you want her to step.
And how is that
accomplished?
I'll show you.
I'll lead.
Now you'll notice that
I don't just repeat
the same pattern over and over.
I improvise.
Now you lead.
That's good.
Now look up, Data.
Look into my eyes.
You're holding me too tight.
This is a very complex
set of variables
to coordinate, Doctor.
You are doing fine.
Now, smile.
Act like you're
enjoying yourself.
NURSE:
Dr. Crusher, please
report to Sick Bay.
Is it Lieutenant Juarez?
Yes, Doctor, her contractions
are now one minute apart.
I'm on my way.
Why don't you, uh...
program up an artificial
dance partner?
And don't be afraid
to experiment.
I will.
Thank you, Doctor.
Computer, create dance partner--
female.
Begin music.
( music starts )
RIKER:
Then just as the headsman swings
the axe and the blade is...
Commander Riker's
easygoing manner
and sense of humor
is fascinating to me.
I believe it to be one reason
he is so popular
among the crew.
It may also be
partly responsible
for his success
in matters of love.
There may be a correlation
between humor and sex.
The need for more research
is clearly indicated.
( console beeping )
Commander.
Picard to the Bridge.
All stop.
Aye, sir.
DATA:
Sir, we have reached
the designated coordinates.
Hold this position.
Long range scan.
Captain, I am
detecting a ship
in the Neutral Zone.
Configuration...
Romulan warbird.
Yellow Alert.
Hail the warbird,
Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
They are responding.
Text only.
We are to proceed
to the agreed
coordinates.
Set course 037 mark 005,
warp four.
Take us into the Neutral Zone,
Ensign.
Captain, the warbird
is holding position.
In three minutes, we will be
within phaser range.
Red Alert.
( alarm blaring )
I trust my crew, Ambassador.
They will take
no provocative action
unless I order them.
Hold position
on these coordinates.
Slow to half impulse.
Open a channel.
Open.
I am Ambassador T'Pel.
I am Admiral Mendak.
There is no
established protocol
for a meeting of this nature.
The logical course
is that I transport
aboard your ship and
begin the negotiations.
Yes.
Captain, I note
your defensive systems
have been activated.
As have yours.
It was not meant
as an accusation.
Indeed, I salute
your show of strength.
Ambassador, we are honored
by your presence.
You may transport aboard
at your convenience.
The honor is mine.
Have your transporter room
stand by.
I will beam
aboard their ship
with no further delay.
Ambassador, I urge you
once more to reconsider.
The Enterprise can
accommodate a
Romulan delegation
without sacrificing
our security or...
Captain Picard, I find
your argument illogical.
Please carry out
my instructions.
Picard to Chief O'Brien.
O'Brien here.
Prepare to transport
Ambassador T'Pel to
the Romulan vessel.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, maintain
a lock on her signal
once she's aboard.
At the first sign of
trouble, I want to be
able to bring her back.
Understood.
Transporter activated.
( console beeping insistently)
Captain...
O'BRIEN:
Transporter emergency!
I'm losing her signal.
Boosting power
to autosequencers.
Engaging computer override.
O'Brien, what happened
down there?
I'm losing the pattern.
Trying to reestablish.
I'm sorry, sir.
I wasn't able
to retrieve the signal.
The Ambassador is dead.
DATA:
Second Officer's Personal Log,
supplemental.
The risks aboard a starship
are accepted by all who serve
but I have never failed
to observe
a deep emotional response
to the loss of a comrade.
It is at times like this
that I greatly miss the ability
to share human feelings.
The signal lock
wasn't broken, sir.
I had just entered
the transfer sequence
when the Ambassador's
pattern began to break up.
I tried to switch to
emergency manual control
but the pattern
deteriorated too
quickly and...
Captain, there is no prior
record of this type of accident
occurring aboard a starship.
Backup systems and safeguards
are designed to prevent
just such an occurrence.
I can't find any system flaws
in the unit, Captain.
The engineering status
reports were all normal
none of the backups
were activated
and the autosequencers were
all functioning normally.
Any prior malfunctions
on this transporter unit?
No, sir.
In fact, we replaced
the transition coil
only last week.
Could there have been
some sort of
interference
from the Romulans?
Nothing that I could see.
The shields were down.
There was no power
interruption
no subspace bias.
I want this unit pulled
and its systems checked again
and I want a level-one
diagnostic on all transporters.
Yes, sir.
Her molecular structure
dissipated instantly
once the pattern was lost.
There were some organic
compounds left on the pad
but there wasn't enough
material to do an autopsy.
To die...
on a transporter.
Hardly a fitting end
for one of the Federation's
most honored diplomats.
WORF:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Admiral Mendak is hailing.
He wishes to speak with you.
( sighs )
We're still waiting, Captain.
Is there a problem?
PICARD:
There's been an accident.
Ambassador T'Pel has been killed
in a transporter malfunction.
What kind of malfunction?
We are still investigating that.
As soon as...
I should have known
the Federation
wasn't serious
about this conference.
Admiral, I assure you
the Federation
places the highest priority
on this mission and its goal.
Well played, Captain.
Well played.
Starfleet opposes
normalization of relations
with the Romulan Empire
and so you are ordered
to create... an "accident."
You are mistaken.
I am ready and willing
to discuss the establishment
of full diplomatic relations
under the same terms
as Ambassador T'Pel.
A generous offer, since you know
that we were willing
to negotiate only with T'Pel.
I salute you again, Captain.
It was a maneuver
worthy of a Romulan.
I suggest we both
leave the Neutral Zone
before there
is another... "accident."
Set course
for Federation territory.
Warp two.
Engage.
Mr. Data, I want you to take
charge of this investigation.
Study computer logs,
sensor information, everything.
I refuse to believe that this
was a simple malfunction.
Aye, sir.
Captain Picard was the person
who first interested me
in the works
of Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
I have subsequently
become a great admirer
of the fictional detective
Sherlock Holmes
and his ability
to solve mysteries
by careful examination
of the available evidence.
I have found
Holmes' methodology
of deductive reasoning
to be quite useful.
One of his adages is
that, once you have
eliminated the impossible
whatever remains, however
improbable, must be the truth.
I'm sorry,
I don't have time
to give you another lesson
right now, Data.
That is not my purpose.
I would like to examine
the remains of Ambassador T'Pel
left on the transporter pad.
I'm working on the report
right now.
Have you
compared the genetic code
with the Ambassador's last
recorded transporter ID traces?
No, that's not
standard procedure. Why?
I could be chasing an untamed
ornithoid without cause.
A wild goose chase?
All right.
Computer, access the transporter
ID trace for Ambassador T'Pel.
All right.
There's the genetic record
of the Ambassador
when she beamed aboard the
Enterprise.
Now, the breakdown
of the organic material
found on the transporter pad
should be identical.
Mitochondrial structure
fits the general parameters.
No change
in the nucleotide bases.
Hmm, there's
a slight discrepancy
in the base pair sequence.
Chemically, these
are identical, however
the organic sample
from the transporter
is showing numerous
single-bit errors--
like replicated material.
Can you postulate
an explanation
for the discrepancy?
I'd say the DNA was either
mutated by the transporter
during the re-materialization
process...
A supposition not supported
by the transporter records.
...or these aren't the remains
of the Ambassador.
The only abnormality
found during my investigation
was a temporary increase in the
matter-to-energy signal ratio.
Due to the circumstances
I decided to investigate
the possibility
that a second transporter signal
had caused the fluctuation.
Although this is
highly improbable
it was the only
remaining theory.
A second transporter signal--
from where?
From the Devoras.
Romulan transporters operate
on a similar subspace frequency
to our own.
With only minor adjustments,
they can be made
to simulate our own
transporter carrier wave.
Are you saying they beamed
the Ambassador off our own pad?
While simultaneously
a small amount
of genetically similar material
was left
in the Ambassador's place.
To make us believe
that she had died
as a result of the malfunction.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Worf,
where is the Devoras now?
WORF:
The ship is still
in the Neutral Zone.
On course 079 mark 125.
Speed: warp two.
Heading for home.
The safest and most logical
decision in this situation
is to contact Starfleet
and await further
instructions.
However,
based on past experience
I project only a 17% chance
Captain Picard will choose
that alternative.
Red Alert.
All hands
stand to
battle stations.
( alarm blaring )
Lay in an intercept course
to the Romulan ship.
Shields up.
Load all torpedo bays.
Stand by phasers.
Warp factor eight.
Engage.
Open a channel to the Devoras.
Aye, sir.
No response.
DATA:
The Devoras is dropping
out of warp, sir.
Their weapon systems
are powering up.
Go to impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Message coming in, sir.
PICARD:
On screen.
Captain, you agreed to leave
the Neutral Zone without...
Admiral Mendak
you have taken
our Ambassador captive.
I can assure you
there is no one being held
captive aboard this ship.
We know about
the transporter "malfunction"
and that you are holding
Ambassador T'Pel.
WORF:
Captain
Romulan warbird
de-cloaking to starboard.
I suggest you leave...
now.
Admiral, it is my responsibility
to protect the lives
of Federation citizens.
I will not permit
this abduction to succeed.
Captain, you're not going
to start an incident
which might...
Admiral Mendak, I will take
whatever action is necessary
to obtain the return
of the Ambassador.
In the game of poker,
there is a moment
when a player must decide
if an opponent
is being deceptive or actually
holds a winning hand.
This decision is based
not only on the odds
but also on an appraisal
of the man--
is he bluffing,
or does he have the cards?
MENDAK:
Fortunately, Captain
I am not ready to start a war...
today.
T'Pel.
Subcommander Selok, actually.
A spy.
A patriot, Captain.
She has performed her
service to the Empire
with distinction.
Thank you for your help,
Captain.
MENDAK:
You see now that we are not
holding one of your citizens
and we thank you for returning
our sister to us
but my patience has limits.
The game is over.
I expect you to
leave peacefully...
now.
Captain, long-range sensors
detect three Romulan warbirds
entering the sector.
Some days you
get the bear
and some days,
the bear gets you.
Reverse course.
Take us back into
Federation territory.
Warp six.
Engage.
Keiko, I need your help.
I have offended you
and need to find a way
to rectify my mistake.
I am not sure
what to do.
You haven't offended me.
I should not
have interfered.
It would be best
if I apologize.
if you got dressed.
For the wedding.
Oh.
But...?
Come here.
I have the most
beautiful carnation
for the father
of the bride.
Now, don't be nervous.
I am not nervous.
I am confused.
( chuckles )
( Japanese classical
court music plays )
( music ends )
Since the days of the
first wooden sailing ships
all Captains have enjoyed
the happy privilege
of joining together two people
in the bonds
of matrimony, and so...
it is my honor to unite you,
Keiko Ishikawa
and you, Miles Edward O'Brien,
together in matrimony...
There are still
many human emotions
I do not fully comprehend--
anger, hatred, revenge--
but I am not mystified
by the desire to be loved...
( applause and cheers )
...or the need for friendship.
These are things
I do understand.
( applause continues )
Congratulations!
( dance music plays )
( baby gurgling )
I was looking
for Dr. Crusher.
Shh.
DATA:
The Juarez child?
PICARD:
Mm-hmm... a boy.
At the same time we
were facing destruction
this small miracle
was taking place.
( softly ):
Welcome aboard.
All systems normal, sir.
We are on course
for Adelphous IV.
Engineering is realigning
the main deflector dish
Sick Bay reports
Lieutenant Umbato
broke two ribs
during a holodeck exercise
and sensors continue to gather
long-range information
on the Murasaki quasar.
Very well.
I have the Bridge.
Aye, sir.
If being human
is not simply a matter
of being born flesh and blood
if it is instead a way
of thinking, acting and
feeling
then I am hopeful that one day
I will discover
my own humanity.
Begin night watch.
Until then, Commander Maddox,
I will continue
learning, changing, growing
and trying to become more
than what I am.