Captain's Log,
Stardate 44429.6.
We are on a mapping survey
near the Cardassian sector.
It has been nearly a year
since a peace treaty ended
the long conflict between
the Federation and Cardassia.
Captain, we
are nearing
the periphery
of Sector 21503.
Be on the lookout
for a Cardassian patrol ship,
Mr. Worf.
They should be hailing
us soon.
Even with the treaty,
they're still skittish
about protecting
their border.
Last time
I was in this sector
I was on the Stargazer
running at warp speed
ahead of a Cardassian warship.
TROI:
Running,
Captain?
You? That's hard to believe.
Believe it.
I'd been sent to make
preliminary overtures
to a truce, and I'd
lowered my shields
as a gesture of goodwill.
The Cardassians
were not impressed.
They had taken out
most of my weapons
and damaged the impulse engines
before I could regroup and run.
The Cardassians have no honor.
I do not trust them.
They're our allies now,
Mr. Worf.
We have to trust them.
Trust is earned, not given away.
I hope their scout ship
makes contact soon.
It's not a good idea to stay
too long on a Cardassian border
without making
your intentions known.
What... what is it?
Kelp buds, plankton loaf
and sea berries.
Oh.
Sweetheart
I'm not a fish.
It's very healthy.
I had this every morning
when I was growing up.
What? No muffins or oatmeal
or corned beef
and eggs?
For breakfast?
Keiko
I've been thinking.
You've been introducing me
to all this wonderful food
that you're
accustomed to.
I'd like to do the same.
Isn't that
what marriage is about?
Sharing?
What kind of foods?
Scalloped potatoes,
mutton shanks
oxtails
and cabbage.
Kind of heavy.
Oh, you'll love it.
I promise.
Oh, I can still remember
the aromas
when my mother was cooking.
She cooked?
Oh, she didn't believe
in a replicator.
She thought real food
was more nutritious.
She handled real meat?
She touched it and cut it?
Yeah, like a master chef.
She was
fantastic.
Of course, I'll have to use
the replicator.
I'll make something special
for you tonight.
You'll love it.
I promise.
Okay.
Maybe I'll have something
special for you tonight too.
Mmm...
( both chuckling )
( explosion )
Something's wrong.
COMPUTER:
Red Alert.
Take emergency stations.
( alarm blares )
Cardassian ship
preparing to
fire again, sir.
Increase power
to the forward shields.
( explosion )
Hail them again,
Mr. Worf.
What the hell
is he doing?
Damage report.
Minor damage to
secondary hull
before we put up
our shields, sir.
No casualties.
Structural
integrity intact.
LA FORGE:
Engineering to Bridge.
Starboard power coupling
is down.
( explosion )
Evasive action--
Delta sequence.
Ready phasers, Mr. Worf.
Delta evasion plan initiated.
Limit targets
to engines and shields.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Ready.
Fire.
Direct hit, sir.
Moderate damage
to their aft shield generators.
Continue phaser fire.
DATA:
Multiple
hits, sir.
Power failure
in their forward shields.
WORF:
The Cardassian ship
is standing down, sir.
Well, let's see
if they'll answer
our hail now, Mr. Worf.
Frequency open.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
I am Gul Macet,
of the Cardassian ship Trager.
Why have you fired on us?
A curious question, Captain.
In war,
one attacks one's enemies.
There is a treaty
between our peoples.
Perhaps that fact was unknown
to the Federation starship
which destroyed our space
station in the Cuellar system
two days ago.
Federation starship?
Attacked an unarmed
science station.
They had barely enough time
to send an emergency signal
before they were incinerated.
Gul Macet, the Federation
and the Cardassians
have struggled too hard
for peace
to abandon it so easily.
We are not the ones
who have abandoned it, Captain.
Let me talk to my superiors,
find out what is behind this.
Give me one hour.
The alternative is for us
to continue firing
at one another.
And in such a contest,
you would be
at a disadvantage.
Very well.
One hour.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain, we've confirmed
your report.
It was the Starship Phoenix
under the command
of Benjamin Maxwell.
Ben Maxwell...
but he's one of Starfleet's
finest Captains.
He... he must have
had provocation.
I wish we knew.
He's gone on silent running.
Doesn't answer
our communiqués.
Then he's still
in Cardassian space?
The station he destroyed
was in Sector 21505.
You're the nearest starship.
We want you to go in
and find him.
Will the Cardassians
cooperate?
They've granted you
safe passage.
We've agreed that you'll take
along a delegation
of observers,
as a show of good faith.
Jean-Luc, I don't have
to tell you
the Federation is not prepared
for a new sustained conflict.
You must preserve the peace
no matter what the cost.
Haden out.
There will be three Cardassians
transporting aboard.
Their Captain, Gul Macet,
and two of his aides.
My intention is to be
as open as possible with them.
Allow them to share
in our search for the Phoenix.
Captain, it is necessary
to assign them
a security detail.
They're our guests, Mr. Worf.
I don't want them to feel
like prisoners.
RIKER:
I tend to agree with
Mr. Worf, Captain.
I think we should limit their
access while they're on board.
I don't think they need
to have the run of the ship.
At least allow me
to post guards
in some of the sensitive areas
of the ship.
Very well.
Let's limit their access
but you instruct your people
they are our guests.
Aye, sir.
Counselor,
I want you to stay
as close to the crew
as possible.
Some of them may feel
uncomfortable
with Cardassians on board.
I don't want any incidents.
Yes, Captain.
Mr. Data, is there
anyone else on board
who served previously
with Captain Benjamin Maxwell?
Accessing.
Chief O'Brien served
under his command
aboard the
Rutledge, sir.
PICARD:
Indeed.
Number One, will you
and the Counselor
meet our guests
in Transporter Room Three?
And inform Chief O'Brien
I will be calling on him.
Yes, sir.
RIKER:
Welcome
to the Enterprise.
I'm First Officer
William Riker.
Counselor Deanna Troi.
I am Gul Macet.
My aides, Glinn Daro
Glinn Telle.
RIKER:
This is
our Transporter Chief
Mr. O'Brien.
Shall we?
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have entered
Cardassian territory
and are proceeding on our quest
to locate the Phoenix.
And with long-range sensors
we've been scanning a radius
of ten light-years.
We can effectively scan
one sector a day.
We're scanning
Sector 21505 now.
And there's
still no sign
of the Phoenix.
In fact,
you have no assurance
that the ship is still
in Sector 21505.
In fact, we have no idea
where it is.
We thought
the last known coordinates
were a reasonably
good place
to start.
Captain Picard
you can understand
that we are skeptical.
Do you expect us
to believe that
you are using
every means at your disposal
to track down one of your own?
Of course you are concerned,
Gul Macet.
It is precisely
because of that fact
that I have included you
in every aspect
of our effort.
You're present
with my staff.
You're hearing
reports as
I hear them.
Nothing edited,
nothing withheld.
Very well.
PICARD:
Transporter Chief
O'Brien served
with Benjamin Maxwell.
I thought that he might be able
to provide some insights.
Mr. O'Brien,
I understand
that Captain Maxwell lost
his family
during a raid on an outpost.
More like sabotage, sir.
It was on Setlik III.
A squad of Cardassian militia
made a sneak raid on an outpost.
Wiped out close
to 100 civilians.
Then it's revenge he's after.
That's not what I meant.
Maxwell is taking retribution
for his own loss.
Captain Maxwell would never...
Gentlemen, please, let's not
indulge in speculation.
Can we confine
our discussion
to the facts?
Now, Mr. O'Brien...
Worf to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Mr. Worf.
Long-range sensors have located
the Phoenix.
Gul Macet,
will you join me
on the Bridge?
Deck six.
( beeping )
Deck ten.
Your Captain is most impressive.
Yes, he is.
Chief O'Brien
our transporting system
is still operating
with active feed
pattern buffers.
I would like to talk with you
about your technology.
I'll have to get
Commander La Forge's
approval on that.
I understand.
In the meantime
we're going
to your Ten-Forward.
Will you join us?
If my Commander tells me
to discuss the transporter
with you, I will.
If Captain Picard orders me
to tell you everything I know
about Ben Maxwell,
I will.
But who I choose to
spend my free time with
that's my business.
Captain, the Phoenix
is in Sector 21505.
Ensign, set a
course, warp six.
Mr. Worf,
send a message by subspace.
Tell them to prepare
for a rendezvous.
Yes, Captain.
Captain, a
suggestion?
Yes.
We have a number of
ships in Sector 21505.
If you will give us
more precise coordinates
and the ship's coded
transponder frequency
we would be able
to intercept Maxwell
far more quickly
than you.
I'm sure that's true.
However, given
the circumstances
I would prefer to make
the initial contact myself.
I'm sure you would
if the situation
were reversed.
Captain, time
is crucial.
You have a dangerous
man out there
with a huge arsenal
at his command.
If he is intent upon
revenge against my people
he must be stopped
before he can
do more damage.
Captain, so far, we have
an isolated incident.
If I can reach him first
then perhaps
diplomacy can prevail
but if one of your ships
should decide to retaliate
there is a danger
we could lose control
of the situation.
Then you will not give
us the means to find
his precise location?
No, I won't.
O'BRIEN:
There you are.
Potato casserole,
a dish fit for kings.
♪ The minstrel boy
to the war is gone... ♪
( humming )
What's that
you're singing?
What?
Oh, it's just an old song.
A bunch of us used to sing it
together on the Rutledge.
I hadn't thought
about it in years.
What's it about?
Oh, it's about
war and glory.
♪ The minstrel boy
to the war is gone ♪
♪ In the ranks of death
you will find him ♪
♪ His father's sword
he hath girded on ♪
♪ And his wild harp
slung behind him. ♪
Captain Maxwell
always liked that song.
I guess it's all this business
about him and the Cardassians
brought it back
to me.
You know, sitting
with the staff this morning
I could tell
there were people in that room
who still don't like
the Cardassians.
I imagine
that's to be expected.
You do?
Sure, the war lasted
a long time.
That takes its toll on people.
What are these little,
dark things?
Capers.
But the fighting's over now.
Why should anyone still feel...
however they feel?
You fought the Cardassians,
didn't you?
Well, there were some skirmishes
when I was with Captain Maxwell.
Well, how do you feel
about them?
Me?
Well, I feel fine.
I mean, the war's over now.
PICARD:
The pursuing ship
is the Phoenix.
And the other?
It appears to be
a Cardassian
supply ship.
How would
you know that?
We are able to make
that determination.
You can read
our transponder codes.
The important thing
at the moment
is that one of your ships
may be in jeopardy.
Mr. Worf, has there
been any answer to
our communication?
No, Captain.
Put out a repeating message
on all subspace channels.
Priority one communiqué.
Break off your pursuit
immediately.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Gul Macet, you see
we are doing everything
in our power
to reach the Phoenix.
Yes, and accomplishing nothing,
I'm sorry to say.
Can you show me the location
of our other ships?
Mr. Data?
MACET:
There, you see?
We have a warship
which could intercept
the Phoenix before it's too late
if you will give us
the transponder frequency.
Or are you going
to stand there
while our ship
is destroyed, Captain?
Mr. Worf
has there been
any response
to our hails?
No, Captain.
PICARD:
Very well.
Mr. Worf...
relay the prefix codes
of the Phoenix
to the Cardassian warship.
Sir, they
will be able
to dismantle its shields.
The Phoenix
will not have a chance.
I cannot allow Maxwell
to ambush that supply ship.
Mr. Worf, now!
Yes, Captain.
Sir, the Cardassian
warship is moving
on the Phoenix.
Mr. Data, overlay
weapon ranges
of the two ships.
The warship is 300,000
kilometers from the Phoenix.
It is opening fire.
The Phoenix has taken
a direct hit.
The Phoenix
is beginning
evasive maneuvers.
It has positioned
itself outside
the weapons range
of the opposing ship.
The Phoenix has
powered up
both phasers and
photon torpedoes.
The Phoenix is firing
He has destroyed our warship.
Does the supply ship
have any weapons?
Very limited.
Certainly not enough
to defeat
a Nebula-class starship.
DATA:
Sir, the Phoenix is firing
on them.
The warship carried
a crew of 600.
The supply ship,
50.
Mr. Data, estimated time
to intercept with the Phoenix?
At our present speed
of warp four
16 hours, 44 minutes.
Ensign, increase
to warp nine.
Captain.
Chief, I wanted
to talk to you.
Anything I can do, sir.
You know that.
Ben Maxwell--
he must be quite a man.
He's a rare
one, all right.
I count myself
lucky, sir.
I've served with the
two finest Captains
in Starfleet.
From your knowledge
of the man
what has gone wrong?
Well, there's a reason
for what he's doing.
Those Cardassians
were up to something.
I'm sure of it.
When his family was killed,
how did he take it?
I'd say he took it well.
Oh, I know
he was broken up inside.
Who wouldn't be?
But you'd never
know it to see him.
He never missed a minute's duty.
Always had a smile, a joke.
Hmm. I see.
He would never
retaliate out
of vengeance
no matter what
that Cardassian says
They're up to
something, sir.
They're the ones you
should be investigating
not Captain Maxwell.
You don't care for
the Cardassians.
Oh, I like them fine.
It's just...
Well, I know them.
You learn to watch
your back when you're
around those people.
Ben Maxwell has just sent
more than 600 of them
to their deaths.
I don't know
what to say, sir
but he must have had
his reasons.
( sighs )
I think...
when one has been angry
for a very long time
one gets used to it.
And it becomes
comfortable
like...
like old leather.
And finally...
it becomes so familiar
that one can't ever remember
feeling any other way.
Thank you, Chief.
Kanar.
Mind if I join you?
You want another?
And an ale.
Kanar.
I never could develop
a taste for it.
It takes a bit
of getting used to.
I wanted to say I...
I owe you an apology.
I shouldn't have
popped off like that
in the turbolift.
I think...
Here's your ale,
Mr. O'Brien.
This has been hard
on all of us.
I know I'll be happy
when I'm back
on my own ship.
I guess that's true.
I hadn't thought
about that.
I was on Setlik III
with Captain Maxwell
the morning after
the massacre.
We were too late,
of course.
( sighs )
Almost everyone was dead.
That was a terrible mistake.
We were told the outpost
was a launching place
for a massive attack
against us.
The only people left alive
were in an outlying
district of the settlement.
I was sent there
with a squad to
reinforce them.
The Cardassians
were advancing on us...
moving through the streets,
destroying, killing.
I was with a group
of women and children
when two Cardassian soldiers
burst in.
I stunned one of them.
The other one jumped me.
We struggled.
One of the women threw me
a phaser
and I fired.
The phaser was set at maximum.
The man just...
just incinerated there
before my eyes.
I'd never killed
anything before.
When I was a kid
I'd worry
about swatting a mosquito.
It's not you I hate, Cardassian.
I hate what I became
because of you.
( door opens, closes )
I will protest
this, Klingon.
Lieutenant?
He was found
at a computer station on deck 35
attempting to access information
on our weapons systems.
TELLE:
A lie,
Gul Macet.
I was studying
the terminal
interface systems.
They're more
efficient
than ours.
I have no idea
what was in
the files.
What business did you have
going near
one of their computers?
But, Gul Macet,
I meant nothing.
There was no harm done.
Go to your quarters.
You're confined there
for the duration
of this expedition.
As you wish.
Sir.
PICARD:
Mr. Worf,
please accompany him.
WORF:
Gladly, Captain.
Captain, may we
speak in private?
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
( sighs )
I deeply regret
what my aide
has done, Captain.
You have my word
he will be disciplined
upon my return.
You may take whatever action
against him
you feel is appropriate.
I consider the matter closed.
I'm not sure
I would be so generous
in your place, Captain.
Thank you.
If there is to be
a lasting peace, Gul Macet
neither you nor I must allow
any one man
to undermine
our efforts.
There are those who...
crave war--
who need it.
I am not one of them, Captain
and I'm beginning to see
that neither are you.
We have had
our full measure.
The lasting peace begins here
with the two of us.
DATA:
Bridge to Captain.
Picard here.
We have located
the Phoenix, sir.
We will intercept it
in 22 minutes.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44431.7.
We have established
communication
with Captain Maxwell
and he has agreed
to come on board.
Welcome aboard, sir.
I'm Commander Riker,
First Officer.
I know all about
you, Commander.
Fine work you did
with the Borg.
We all owe you
on that one.
Thank you, sir.
O'Brien?
Miles O'Brien?
Hello, Captain.
Good to see
you again.
How are you?
I had no idea you were
on the Enterprise.
This was my tactical officer
on the Rutledge.
Best I ever had.
Thank you, sir.
O'Brien has
the ability
to size up a situation instantly
then come up with options
to fit all contingencies.
Remarkable!
Well, if that's true,
I learned it from you, sir.
( in Irish brogue ):
But you got that silver tongue
by kissing the stone
right?
Well, Commander, best I see
your Captain straight away.
We've got a lot to talk about.
Yes, sir.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
Captain Benjamin Maxwell.
That will be
all, Commander.
Captain.
A pleasure, Captain.
Please sit down.
You must think
I've gone mad.
The thought
had occurred.
Picard, I have to tell you.
I was grateful
when I realized it was you
Starfleet had sent after me--
someone who knows
what it's really
like out here.
I know of nothing out here
that could possibly justify
what you
have done.
Then listen to this.
The Cardassians
are arming again.
That so-called
science station?
Military supply port.
How do you know this?
Information comes my way.
From whom?
Where is your documentation?
I know
what they're doing!
I can smell it.
There's no good reason
for a science station
in the Cuellar system.
But it's
a hell of a strategic site
for a military
transport station--
a jumping-off point
into three Federation sectors.
They're running
supply ships
back and forth.
And nobody's going to tell me
it's for scientific research.
But whatever circumstances
you encountered
why didn't you notify Starfleet?
( scoffs ):
And wait six months
while the bureaucrats
sit around reading reports
trying to figure out
what to do?
They don't know
what's going on out here.
But you should, Picard.
You know what it's like
to be under fire.
You weren't under fire.
Lives were at stake.
Whose lives?
We had to act now!
Why?
Smells musty in here...
like a bureaucrat's office.
You have killed
nearly 700 people
and you have taken us
to the brink of war.
I have prevented war
or at the very least delayed it
a good long time.
The peace treaty was a ruse,
to give them breathing room
time to regroup.
And so, all alone, you decided
to dispose of the treaty.
I took the initiative.
I did what had to be done.
What had to be done?
Hmm? For whom?
Why would a man
with a long
and brilliant service
abandon
the fundamental principles
that he has believed in--
even fought for--
all of his life?
Well, I believe
it is because of what they did
to your wife
and your children.
Not true...
not true.
To avenge
their deaths.
You're a fool, Picard.
History will look at you
and say, "This man was a fool."
I'll accept the judgment
of history.
When it becomes clear
what the Cardassians have done
I will be vindicated.
What the Cardassians have
or have not done is irrelevant.
Irrelevant?!
Then come with me.
Find one of their supply ships
and we'll see
how "irrelevant"
it is.
We're not going after
any more
Cardassian ships.
You're going
to return to your Bridge
and set a course
for Starbase 211.
The Phoenix and the
Enterprise will return
to Federation
space together.
Those are
Starfleet's orders.
I will permit
you the dignity
of retaining your command
during the voyage
but the only alternative
is to put you in the brig
and to tow your ship back
to the Starbase in disgrace.
I will return to my ship.
You understand
your orders?
Yes, Captain.
Mr. Worf, report
to my ready room.
My guest is departing.
Aye, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
With the Phoenix
in close formation
we are proceeding directly
to Starbase 211.
Mr. Data, how long until
we clear Cardassian space?
At our present speed
three hours,
20 minutes, sir.
Mr. Worf, send a message
to Admiral Haden at Starfleet.
Inform them of
our projected time of arrival.
Aye, sir.
Captain, the Phoenix
has changed course.
What is he doing?
Ensign, change course to pursue.
( sighs )
Mr. Worf, will you hail
Captain Maxwell?
No response, Captain.
Data, project his new course.
The Phoenix is headed directly
for a Cardassian vessel
.12 light-years
from our location.
He'll attack that ship,
just as he did the others.
PICARD:
Continue the hail,
Mr. Worf.
Priority one message.
Do you know
what that ship might be?
I imagine it's a supply ship
headed for the research station
in the Kelrabi system.
The Phoenix still
does not respond, sir.
Ensign, warp eight.
Overtake him.
Captain, the Phoenix has
accelerated to warp nine.
We will not be able to reach him
before he intercepts
the Cardassian vessel.
Ensign, warp nine.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, arm phasers.
Continue the hail.
Aye, sir.
Captain, Chief O'Brien was
Maxwell's tactical officer.
Get him up here.
DATA:
Sir, the Phoenix has
dropped out of warp.
They have reached
the Cardassian vessel.
RIKER:
Slow to impulse.
Vessels are within visual range.
On screen.
RIKER:
Has the Phoenix
activated
its weapons systems?
DATA:
Negative, sir.
Their phaser banks
are not armed.
What about
the Cardassians?
Sensors are unable
to determine the status
of the Cardassian
defensive systems.
Their ship is running
with a high-powered
subspace field.
Mr. O'Brien,
your former Commander
a Federation Captain,
is about to place me
in the position
of firing on his ship.
I need your knowledge
of the man
how he thinks,
what he's capable of doing.
Aye, sir.
Sir, Captain Maxwell
is hailing us.
On screen.
MAXWELL:
All right, Picard.
You need proof?
You've got it now.
Captain Maxwell, you have
disobeyed a direct order.
Board the ship.
You'll see that everything
I've been saying is true.
The Cardassian vessel
will not be boarded.
You will transport yourself
aboard the Enterprise.
Picard, if you don't board
that ship
I'll destroy it.
And I will use
whatever force is necessary
to prevent you from taking
that action, Captain.
Sir, Captain Maxwell--
if he feels his back
is against the wall
he'll strike.
Captain, the Phoenix
is transferring power
to its shields.
WORF:
They are arming phasers
and loading forward
torpedo bays.
Red Alert.
Seems you were right,
Mr. O'Brien.
Ready phasers,
load torpedoes.
Phasers armed.
Loading forward and
aft torpedo bays.
O'BRIEN:
Sir, let me
beam over.
Try to talk to him.
We served together a long time.
When you've been through
what we have, you tend
to get inside someone.
He might listen.
He'd never lower
his shields
and allow you
to transport on board.
The Phoenix is using
a high-energy sensor system.
It cycles
every 5.5 minutes.
Between cycles,
there's a window
of a 50th of a second.
Trust me.
I can get through.
Make it so.
( doorbell chimes )
Not now!
I'm not armed.
How the devil
did you get over here?
I had the thought
that if we could talk
we could figure a way
out of this mess.
The way out of this is clear.
Talk to Picard.
Get him to board the damn ship.
He won't do that, sir.
But he'd turn his weapons
on a Federation starship
to protect the enemy?
I don't
believe it.
He will.
Count on it.
What the hell has happened
to this war?
Sir...
there is no war.
The war is over.
You're wrong.
The Cardassians live
to make war.
That's what everybody thinks
about the enemy.
That's probably what
they think about us.
We're not
the same at all.
We do not start wars.
We do not make surprise
attacks on manned outposts.
We do not butcher women and
children in their homes.
Children...
who never had the
chance to grow up.
You were with me on Setlik.
You saw
what they did.
Yes, sir.
What was the name
of that fellow
who always hung around you
like a puppy?
Will Kayden.
Stompie.
Stompie!
As cool under fire
as a mountain lake.
Yes, sir.
He died at Setlik,
didn't he?
Yes, sir.
What was that song of his?
The one he always sang?
The one I liked?
♪ The minstrel boy
to the war has gone ♪
♪ In the ranks of death
you will find him ♪
BOTH:
♪ His father's sword
he hath girded on ♪
♪ And his wild harp
slung behind him ♪
♪ "Land of song,"
said the warrior bard ♪
♪ "Though all the world
betrays thee ♪
♪ "One sword, at least,
thy rights shall guard ♪
O'BRIEN:
♪ One faithful harp
shall praise thee." ♪
I'm not going to win
this one, am I, Chief?
No, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Captain Maxwell has turned his
ship over to his First Officer
and transported
aboard the Enterprise.
I have confined him to quarters
for the return voyage.
Thank you, Chief.
I'd just like
to say, sir
he was a good man.
What he did was
terribly wrong
I know that now
but I'm still proud
to have served with him.
Thank you, Chief.
And well done.
That'll be all.
Well, his loyalty is admirable
even if it is misplaced.
The loyalty that you would
so quickly dismiss
does not come easily
to my people, Gul Macet.
You have much to learn
about us.
Benjamin Maxwell
earned the loyalty
of those who served
with him.
You know, in war,
he was twice honored
with the Federation's
highest citation
for courage
and valor.
And if he could not find
a role for himself in peace
we can pity him, but we
shall not dismiss him.
You are welcome to
your opinion, Captain.
I, for one, am grateful
he is under lock and key.
One more thing,
Gul Macet.
Maxwell was right.
Those ships were not carrying
scientific equipment, were they?
A research station
within arm's reach
of three Federation sectors?
Cargo ships running
with high-energy
subspace fields
that jam sensors?
If you believe
the transport ship
was carrying
weapons, Captain
why didn't you board it
as Maxwell
requested?
I was here
to protect the peace--
a peace that I firmly believe
is in the interest
of both
our peoples.
If I had attempted
to board that ship
I'm quite certain that you and I
would not be having
this pleasant conversation
and that ships on both sides
would now be arming for war.
Captain, I assure you...
Take this message
to your leaders, Gul Macet.
We'll be watching.