You don't believe in me.
I don't.
What evidence
would you have
of my reality
beyond that of your senses?
I don't know.
Why do you doubt
your senses?
Because...
a little thing
affects them.
A slight disorder
of the stomach
makes them cheats.
You may be a bit
of undigested beef
a blot of mustard,
a crumb of cheese
a fragment
of an underdone potato.
Why, there's more of gravy
than of grave about you
whatever you are.
Humbug, I tell you.
Humbug.
( screaming )
( fearful cry )
Freeze program.
Very well done, Data.
Your performance skills
really are improving.
Your courtesy
is appreciated, sir
but I am aware that I do not
effectively convey the fear
called for in the story.
Well, you've never
known fear, Data
but as an acute
observer of behavior
you should be able
to approximate it.
Sir, that is not
an appropriate basis
for an effective performance.
Not by the standards
set by my mentors.
Your mentors?
Yes, sir.
I have studied
the philosophies
of virtually
every known acting master.
I find myself attracted
to Stanislavsky, Adler, Garnav--
proponents of
an acting technique
known as "The Method."
Method acting, huh?
I'm vaguely familiar with it
but why would you choose
such an old-fashioned approach?
Perhaps because
the technique
requires an actor to seek
his own emotional awareness
to understand the
character he plays.
But, surely, that's
an impossible task
for you, Data.
Sir, I have modified the method
for my own uses.
Since I have
no emotional awareness
to create a performance
I am attempting
to use performance
to create emotional awareness.
I believe if I can learn
to duplicate the fear
of Ebenezer Scrooge
I will be one step closer
to truly understanding humanity.
RIKER:
Captain Picard,
please report to the Bridge.
On my way, Number One.
Data, the moment
that you decided
to stop imitating
other actors
and create your
own interpretation
you were already
one step closer
to understanding
humanity.
We've received
an emergency transmission
from the science station
on Ventax II, sir.
What's the nature
of the emergency?
Uncertain.
The signal was interrupted...
Contact reestablished
with Ventax II, sir.
On screen.
I am Dr. Howard Clark,
director of the science station
here on Ventax II.
Thank you for responding.
Mr. Worf,
can you improve our reception?
The trouble is
at the transmission source, sir.
Dr. Clark, we're barely able to
maintain communication with you.
Can you boost the level
of your power source?
I'm afraid not, Captain.
It's under attack.
Under attack?
There's a mob outside the door
trying to break
into the station.
The planet is in chaos--
lootings, fires
mass hysteria.
These people
are all convinced
that their world is coming
to an end tomorrow.
Please, we must have
your immediate...
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44474.5.
We have reached Ventax II
and are attempting to contact
the Federation science station
which at last report was
under siege by an angry mob.
They are
transmitting again.
On screen,
before we lose contact.
Enterprise.
Enterprise, do you read me?!
Emergency! We need help.
Dr. Clark,
this is Captain Picard.
We are ready to beam you
and your team
on board...
( explosion )
They're in! They're in!
Transporter Room Three
lock onto the science team,
beam them aboard.
I've locked onto Dr. Clark.
I can't pick out the others.
It's a mess down there.
Then beam Dr. Clark aboard
by himself.
Yes, Captain.
Mr. Worf, will you escort him
to my ready room.
Aye, sir.
Number One, try
and make some sense
out of this mess.
The people in Ventax II
live in an agrarian society.
At least, they do now.
What do you mean "now"?
It's an interesting
anthropological question
one we were studying
before the... trouble began.
In the distant past
the Ventaxian culture
had achieved
an extremely, um,
advanced scientific level
but a millennium ago
they turned their backs
on technology.
They reverted
to a simpler existence.
And remained that way
for centuries.
First contact was made
by a Klingon expedition
70 years ago.
Since then,
the new technology's
been available
to the Ventaxians.
They simply are not
interested in it.
Virtually no social problems
can be found on this planet.
In fact, I would have
described their society
as idyllic, until...
Until what, Doctor?
It's hard to believe.
Several years ago, Acost Jared,
the Ventaxian head of state
began to grow
increasingly obsessed
with the legend of Ardra.
With each passing day,
he grew more anxious
and he'd talk
about little else.
"Ardra is coming back.
"Ardra will be here soon.
"We must all leave
before Ardra returns."
And who is this Ardra?
For all intents and purposes...
the devil.
Captain, these people
actually believe
they've sold their souls
to the devil.
Riker to Captain Picard.
Have you located the
science team, Number One?
Evidently, they're
being held hostage.
Hostage?
There's a Ventaxian leader
on the viewscreen,
name of Acost Jared.
Doctor.
Jared, you must secure
the release of my people.
I can't believe
you would allow this.
Howard, my friend, you know
how I abhor all acts of violence
but events
are out of my control.
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Is there nothing you can do?
As the hour of Ardra's return
approaches, fear has overwhelmed
my people.
It has been a thousand years!
The prophecies have come true.
Prophecies?
Ardra's arrival was
supposed to be heralded
with the shaking
of the cities.
Now, there has been a series
of geological tremors
on the planet--
minor quakes.
Nothing extraordinary.
But poorly timed.
There is more.
For several nights, there have
been visions of Ardra.
Again, just as the contract said
would occur before her return.
Visions? You mean dreams.
No. She has appeared.
I, myself, have seen her.
Jared, tell your people,
if the hostages are released
I am prepared
to offer Federation assistance
should this...
this Ardra return.
I'm afraid it will not matter.
They know your weapons are
useless against her, Captain.
I will make inquiries
concerning the hostages.
The innocent should not suffer
for our sins
but I can make no promises.
This situation is
deteriorating, Captain.
The people are reaching
levels of anxiety
that could lead to suicide.
Mr. Data, what do we
know about this Ardra?
She is a cornerstone
of Ventaxian theology.
It seems Ardra came to Ventax II
and promised 1,000 years
of peace and prosperity
for a price--
upon her return
she would enslave
the entire population.
In Ventaxian culture,
it is considered bad luck
to speak her
name out loud.
CLARK:
There are ancient scrolls
concerning Ardra
that are stored
in the Atheneum Vaults.
Scholars study them.
They've been of little
public interest
until recently.
I think I should meet
with this Acost Jared.
He's still our best hope
for a release of the hostages.
I'll arrange to have him
transported on board.
No, I'm going
down to the planet myself.
Sir, you'd run the risk
of being taken
as an additional hostage.
Mr. Worf, you and Mr. Data
will accompany me.
Mr. O'Brien can keep a lock
on our communicators.
He can pull us
out if necessary.
Yes, sir.
PICARD:
Counselor, I want
you to come, too.
( screams
and distant explosions )
Captain Picard, you
shouldn't have come.
Your life is
in danger here.
You must calm your people.
There is no reason
for panic.
No reason?
If these tremors
have frightened them
leading to this hysteria
over Ardra
let us reassure them.
We have scanned the
tectonic stress patterns
of your planet's crust.
There is no evidence
that the quakes
pose any kind of threat.
No, no, no.
The threat is from Ardra.
You cannot understand.
If you can at least help us
to locate our people.
( rumbling )
She is here.
Nonsense. It is only...
Time's up.
( people screaming )
I'm disappointed.
I expected my tenants
to take better care
of my property.
Ardra, most powerful one
I am Jared,
leader of Ventax II.
I take responsibility
for all that displeases you.
Please, do not
punish my people.
Punish? Who said anything
about punishing?
I merely expect your end
of our contract to be upheld.
Thank you, Ardra.
And don't talk like some
ancient prophet around me
with "thees" and "thous"
and "most powerful ones."
It was appealing
for a few centuries
but I bore easily.
And stop cowering.
When I want you on your knees,
I'll let you know.
Much better.
A fine example
for the others.
Who would you be?
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation Starship
Enterprise.
Keep up
the good work.
Now, the first thing we'll need
is an accounting
of all you've been
accumulating for me.
This form will provide
guidelines
for a full census
of the population
with emphasis on productivity
and economic forecasts.
Who are you?
My, you are forceful,
aren't you?
Good. I like my men
to be forceful
at least, at the start.
If your intention
is to intimidate
you're not succeeding.
That's all right.
I like a challenge.
TROI:
An entire planet
has been terrorized
because of the suggestion
that you're going
to enslave the population.
Well, it's true.
Of course, I wouldn't put
it so melodramatically.
It's just a
standard contract
with an unusually
long term.
So you do purport to be
the mythic figure Ardra?
I have many names,
my pale friend.
I am Mendora
in the Berussian Cluster.
Torak to the Drellians.
The Klingons call me Fek'lhr.
You are not Fek'lhr.
Ah, but I am.
I am the Guardian
of Gre'thor
where the dishonored go
when they die.
But here on Ventax II,
I am called Ardra.
The same Ardra
who negotiated a contract
with these people ten
centuries ago today.
Oh, you doubt me.
A non-believer.
Really, Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation Starship
Enterprise
no doubt you have
traveled the galaxy
encountered a diverse
universe of creatures.
Is there no room
for the likes of me?
I've encountered many
who are more credibly to be
called the devil than you.
The devil.
Now there's one I haven't
heard in a long time.
You claim you visited
this planet 1,000 years ago
and negotiated a contract?
That's correct.
I would like to see
that contract.
The scrolls of Ardra, Captain.
A long-winded
description
of a very simple
business arrangement.
I did away with their wars,
famine and economic ruin
and provided them
1,000 years of paradise.
My terms were clearly stated.
They went into this
with their eyes open.
I'm sure you'll find
everything is in order.
You won't mind if I don't
take your word for it.
Jared, with your permission
I'd like Mr. Data to review
these scrolls thoroughly.
It is no longer
my decision, Captain.
I have intrigued you,
haven't I, Picard?
I am only here
to secure the release
of the Federation hostages.
Hostages?
Is this true?
Uh... yes, Ardra.
Panic gripped the people
as the time of your return
grew closer.
Yes, I do have
that effect on people.
See that the hostages
are released-- now!
Immediately.
Let us not cloud this
with bit players, Picard.
You will not leave because
you find me irresistible.
Enterprise, advise Dr. Clark
that the hostages
are being released.
This is Clark.
You did it, Captain.
Thank goodness.
Goodness had nothing
to do with it.
Three to beam up.
Mr. Data will remain
on the planet's surface.
Data, I want
a complete report
on the contents
of these documents.
I refuse to abandon
this planet to that woman.
Energize.
Could she be another refugee
from the Q Continuum?
For that matter,
could she be Q?
Q would never bother
with contracts.
Or economic
forecasts.
I noticed that, too, Counselor.
I had the distinct
impression
of being in the presence of a...
a flimflam artist.
WORF:
But her powers?
Her powers are,
at the best, unclear.
Think about it, Mr. Worf.
Transporter
technology
can make things
appear and disappear.
The illusion that she
can transform herself
into a Klingon creature
could be created
by holographic projection.
CLARK:
And creating
a minor tremor
could be the result
of a low-frequency tractor beam
projected against
the tectonic plates.
We are capable of recreating
all of these events.
It's just that she
dresses them up
and she delivers them
with more dramatic flair.
Like a magician.
Exactly.
TROI:
She has an incredibly
focused mind.
It was virtually impossible
to sense any deception.
Or anything else,
for that matter.
The best magicians
will never let you see
what's up their sleeve,
Counselor.
She must be tapping into
some sort of power source
to produce those effects.
She's not hiding
that up her sleeve.
Number One, I want
you and Mr. Worf
to run high-resolution scans
of this star system.
Look for a ship,
a base of operations
anything large enough
to generate
that power.
Mr. La Forge,
accompany Dr. Clark
back to the science station.
See if you can trace
the origin
of these tremors.
Your chair offers a lovely view
of my planet, Picard.
Come, sit with me.
Either leave my Bridge
or I will remove you
by force.
By force?
( laughing )
You disappoint me.
You didn't strike me
as that sort, Picard.
But, by all means, try.
Mr. Worf?
I was really hoping
you'd try it yourself.
Transporter Room Three,
lock onto the intruder
and transport her
to the planet's surface.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, put up the shields
until further notice.
Yes, sir, Captain,
whatever you say.
We are not impressed
with your magic tricks.
I pity you.
We live in a universe of magic
which, evidently,
you cannot see.
( door opening )
Ah, my pale friend
has returned.
Have you finished
examining
the contract?
I have, sir.
Report, Mr. Data.
The contract agrees to deliver
the people of Ventax II
into the personal
servitude of Ardra
after 1,000
years of peace.
I have compared
the terms
to the body of laws
which govern the planet.
The language of the agreement
is correct in every detail, sir.
Such speed and accuracy.
You're much too talented
to be human.
I am an android.
Android? Of course.
How wonderful--
an unexpected bonus.
Bonus?
Yes.
When the contract came to term
I gained clear title
to the planet--
anything on the surface,
in the air, or...
in orbit.
So, you see,
the Enterprise belongs
to me now as well.
( chuckles )
I am afraid the contract could
be interpreted
in that way, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Although I consider this
woman's claim upon my ship
to be an empty threat,
it has further inspired
my determination to expose her
for the fraud she is.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wish to see me, sir?
Yes, Mr. Data.
A wise man once said
"There is a sucker
born every minute."
Barnum, sir. P.T.
I've been examining
the dynamics
of what used to be called
"the con game."
Quite fascinating--
worthy of your
study, Data.
Sir, do you
believe Ardra is--
to use the vernacular--
a con artist?
Yes, I do, Data.
And I believe it is our job
to out-con the con artist.
Sir, I must point out
that the Ventaxians
did have 1,000 years
of peace and tranquility
as promised by Ardra.
We can only speculate
what happened on that planet
1,000 years ago.
Maybe a Ventaxian leader
saw the destruction
of his society at hand
and he conceived
this "contract of Ardra"
to motivate change.
Or maybe there was
an Ardra of some sort
who was the basis
for this mythology.
Who knows?
The point is...
that somehow a fundamental
theology was created
which transformed
this society
but in the process
of change
created this latent fear
which has been passed down
through generations.
Data, from your
own experience
of performing
Ebenezer Scrooge
you're aware how fear can be
a very powerful motivator.
Indeed, sir.
In the story,
the spirits used fear
to motivate Scrooge
to reform his character.
And in the hands of a con artist
fear can be used to motivate
obedience, capitulation
the exploitation
of innocent people
and that is what I believe
has happened here
and I intend
to prove that.
I need to find a loophole--
some way of challenging
the validity
of this contract.
Sir, the language
of the contract
seems carefully chosen
to avoid any loopholes.
Check it again, Mr. Data
and check every Ventaxian
legal precedent
for the last 1,000 years.
We'll talk again
in the morning.
Aye, sir.
( wind whistling )
Picard to Bridge.
Intruder alert.
Oh, I've arranged
for a bit of privacy.
( buzzing )
Just the two of us.
( seductive laughter )
This is becoming very tiresome.
Oh, come now, Picard.
You know
you find me tantalizing.
Give in to your desires.
You know, there's nothing
about you I find
tantalizing.
On the contrary I find
you obvious and vulgar.
Easily fixed.
I can be
your ideal woman, Picard--
prim and proper
and chaste
until I succumb
to your charms.
Or would your fantasies
turn more toward
a professional woman?
One, perhaps, who wears
a Starfleet uniform?
Perhaps I could even be...
...someone close at hand,
yet unattainable.
I can do anything
for you, Captain...
Anything you could
ever imagine.
I could give you a night that
would light fire
in your dreams until you die
and you would reject me?
Oh, yes.
You shall regret that.
I think not.
Oh, but you will.
Captain Picard.
Captain, I-I wasn't
expecting you here.
Neither was I.
La Forge to Enterprise.
Go ahead.
Worf, Captain
Picard is here.
You'd better transport him
back on board.
The Captain? But I have no...
PICARD:
It's all right, Mr. Worf.
Ardra somehow
transported me here.
Will you beam me
directly to my quarters?
Aye, sir.
We're locked onto you.
Transporter is malfunctioning,
Captain.
Some sort of interference.
Checking.
Just have Mr. Data
fetch me in a shuttle
and have him bring along
a uniform.
Did you say "uniform"?
Yes, I did.
Aye, sir.
Mr. La Forge and Dr. Clark
have made no headway.
Commander Riker
and Lieutenant Worf
have picked nothing up
on their scans.
Sir, I believe
I have found
an obscure precedent
in Ventaxian law
which may be of interest.
Yes?
The case involves
a contract dispute
over services rendered
by a Klingon craftsman
on the construction
of a Ventaxian home.
Because the dispute
involved an alien culture
the parties decided
that arbitration
rather than the courts,
should resolve the issue.
Both parties agreed
to chose an arbitrator.
It is the only known case
involving an alien claimant.
That's exactly what I needed.
Well done, Data.
Shuttlecraft One to Enterprise.
Prepare for docking sequence.
RIKER:
Proceed, Shuttle One.
( consoles beeping )
Enterprise?
Enterprise,
do you read me?
Enterprise, come in.
I cannot locate the Enterprise
anywhere within one light-year
of the planet, sir.
I don't believe Ardra
is capable of transporting
the Enterprise
a light-year away.
Keep hailing
them, Mr. Data.
Repeat on all
frequencies.
Hey, I think
we found something here.
There's a sudden jump
in Z-particle readings
just about the time
the Enterprise disappeared.
Where did it
originate?
It was too brief
to pinpoint.
But it could suggest
a hidden power source.
Gentlemen, we need
to find that source
if we are to defeat this woman.
Well, if you can get
her to perform
a few more
magic tricks like that one
we just might be able
to track it down.
So, I trust you have
a bit more respect for me now.
What have you done
with my ship?
I've done nothing
with your ship.
My ship is safely
in my possession.
I do not recognize your
claim on the Enterprise
nor on this world
for that matter
and in accordance with
Ventaxian legal precedent
I call for an
arbitration.
An arbitration?
There's nothing
here to arbitrate.
PICARD:
Oh, but there is.
You're a fraud, madam,
and I intend to prove
that you could
not have effected
the changes that took
place on this planet.
Do you not believe
what you see
with your own eyes?
Your ship is
gone, Captain.
An illusion.
Magicians have been
making things of all sort
disappear for ages.
Oh, you underestimate me
but then, most people do,
until it's too late.
But if you are
who you say you are
then you have
nothing to lose.
I also have
nothing to gain.
I already have possession
of this planet
and your ship.
I am prepared to offer
an added incentive.
If you win...
I'll take you to the
ruins of Ligillium.
The Zaterl emerald?
You know where it is?
Yes, I do.
Oh...
You are too
clever, Captain
but I have
enough jewels.
If you wish
this foolish arbitration
I will choose my own prize.
And what
would that be?
You.
By all rights, your
body is already mine
but I want more.
I want your heart,
your mind, your soul
and I want you to give them
to me without resistance
of your own free will.
So, do you still
wish to pursue
this most dangerous game?
I agree to your terms.
Oh, Picard, I will
enjoy you morning,
noon and night.
But... we must agree
to an arbitrator.
Very well.
I choose Mr. Data.
Any objections?
But Mr. Data is a member
of my crew.
Of my crew
and he's an android.
He is incapable
of deceit or bias.
He has no feelings to get
in the way of his judgment.
Ardra, before
he responds
may I have a word
in private with
Captain Picard?
Sir, I request
you reject me
as an arbitrator.
Why?
Ardra is right.
If I am chosen, I will
perform my duties
without bias or sentiment.
I cannot guarantee
I will deliver
a verdict in your favor.
Data, where else on this planet
can I find someone
she cannot intimidate?
Sir, I will have to follow
the rules of conduct
for a Ventaxian jurist.
I understand.
You'll make a fine judge.
1,000 years ago,
our planet was dying.
Overcrowded and dangerous
city-states
warred unceasingly
with each other.
The air and water were polluted
with industrial waste
and there was a constant threat
of starvation and epidemic.
Then what happened?
And then... you came.
Objection.
There is no conclusive evidence
that this woman
ever visited
this planet 1,000 years ago.
And I suppose you want
a thousand-year-old witness?
That would be acceptable.
Jared, in the contract
does it specify
how you would know me
when I return?
Yes, by the date.
Anything else?
By the shaking of the cities
and by the visions.
And all of these
occurred on schedule?
Yes.
Thank you.
Your Honor, I submit that I
have established my identity
as stated
by the contract.
Captain Picard
my interpretation
of Ventaxian law
suggests that,
under these circumstances
this is acceptable.
Your objection is overruled.
But, Your Honor...
Sir
I have ruled.
Please sit down.
You may proceed.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Now, when I first
set foot on Ventax II
what did I offer
your people?
According to the scrolls
you offered us 1,000 years
of peace and prosperity
if we would promise
to surrender ourselves to you
at the end of the term.
And why do you think they
would strike such a bargain?
We had nothing to lose.
There was no hope in sight.
Until I came along.
Objection!
I withdraw the
observation.
No further questions.
Your Honor, nothing in this
testament proves that Ardra
had the power to affect
the lives of the Ventaxians.
My opponent has failed
to prove her case
and I move that her claim
be summarily dismissed.
I find no cause to invalidate
the contract at this time.
The arbitration
will continue.
Your Honor, Captain Picard,
as a new visitor to my planet
has been a consistent doubter
of my abilities.
I would like
to ask him
a few questions,
if I may.
DATA:
It is highly
irregular
to question
the opposing advocate
but I see no reason to deny it.
Proceed.
Please do not take any offense
to these questions, Captain.
You know how fond I am of you.
Objection.
Sustained.
The advocate will refrain
from expressing
personal affections
for her opponent.
You do not believe
my powers are real, do you?
No, I don't.
Then, sir, may I ask you
to explain this?
( rumbling )
You are out of order.
Or this?
The advocate will refrain from
making her opponent disappear.
Or this?
( growls )
Can you explain it, Picard?
Any more disruptions
and I will rule you
in contempt of court.
Is that understood?
I am sorry, Your Honor
but can you
explain it, Picard?
Yes or no?
No.
I rest my case, Your Honor.
( chuckles )
The decay rate
of these Z-particles
make it almost impossible
to trace the source.
I'm correlating
the particle trajectories.
They're beginning to align.
Wait a minute.
( chuckling )
I have coordinates.
34 degrees north, 62 degrees
east, at an altitude
of 210 kilometers.
That would
put it in orbit, uh,
above the Western
magnetic pole.
Running visual scan.
Nothing.
Uh-uh. This time,
I don't buy the magic.
Something's got to be there.
Jared, you've described
quite thoroughly
the history of your people
before and after
Ardra's first visit
but I am a little unclear
about the change itself.
Did Ardra simply...
snap her fingers
and transform the planet
into this paradise?
No. The changes
occurred gradually
over a long period of time.
Did she personally
form the government
that so peacefully ruled
this planet for a millennium?
No.
Historical records
indicate
a council
was convened
to assess our options.
They drew up
a new constitution
which the population
later ratified.
I see.
So she advised this council?
No.
No?
Then she must have destroyed
all the weapons on the planet.
No, our leaders
did that
and they signed a treaty
of non-aggression.
Well, then,
let's move on
to the environmental gains
on Ventax II.
How were they accomplished?
We shifted
our economy
from an industrial
to an agrarian base.
It was more ecologically sound.
But Ardra must have purified
the polluted water and air.
No, the record shows
there were a series of
initiatives covering everything
from atmospheric contaminants
to... waste disposal.
Did she not even pick up
one piece of trash?
Ardra had left Ventax II
before the environmental
reforms began.
Forgive me,
but it sounds as if...
with a lot of courage
and hard work
your ancestors changed
this world all by themselves.
Objection. The advocate
is drawing conclusions.
Sustained. I will
draw my own conclusions
if you do not mind... sir.
No further questions.
Rebuttal?
Just two questions.
Is there any doubt
in your mind
any doubt at all-- that if I
had not intervened
the terrible conditions here
would have
continued?
I remind you
that you're under oath.
No doubt at all.
Then, as former head of state
for the Ventaxian people
you are satisfied
that I fulfilled
my part of the bargain?
Yes, Ardra.
Thank you.
Your Honor,
what more can be said?
Both sides agree
the terms of the contract
have been fulfilled.
Captain Picard, do you have
any further evidence to present
before I render
judgment?
( door closes )
I believe my associate,
Mr. La Forge
may be bringing the answer
to that question.
I request
a recess.
Hi, Data.
Geordi.
One hour recess
is granted.
( bangs gavel )
( door closes )
Mr. La Forge, my reputation
as a litigator--
not to mention
my immortal soul--
is in serious jeopardy.
Well, whatever's been
going on over here
gave us exactly
what we needed.
Have you identified
the source of her power?
A cloaked ship.
She has a Romulan
cloaking device?
More likely
a bad copy of one.
We picked it up on
a wavelength stretchout.
And the Enterprise?
Exactly where it's
supposed to be.
Ardra extended
her cloaking
shields around it--
set up a subspace
damping field
to interfere with
normal operations.
I've isolated
the frequency spread
and penetrated
the field.
Can you make contact?
Already have.
This is
what I want to do
but we have
less than an hour...
Jared, you are a wise
and experienced leader
and I assume that you
trust your senses.
Yes, I would say so.
And all your senses tell you
that this woman here
is the most powerful force
on this planet, don't they?
Yes.
And what would you say
if I were to tell you
that she has no powers
whatsoever?
But we have seen her powers
here.
ARDRA:
That's right
and you will again.
Oh, yes-- Ardra's magic.
Jared, would you believe me
if I told you
that I could steal her powers
and perform
the same magic acts
as she does?
I'm sorry, Captain Picard,
but you are not Ardra.
No, that's true.
I'm not Ardra
but I can create tremors
just as she did.
( rumbling )
Objection, Your Honor.
I think he deserves
some leeway.
Overruled.
But that will be
quite enough, Captain.
Of course.
Ardra, will you do the honors
and stop the tremors?
Uh... of course.
Is something the matter?
I like the tremors.
Well, I don't.
PICARD:
Do you recognize
the same old
bag of tricks?
What about this one?
Come back, Ardra,
if you can.
No?
Fine. Allow me.
Of all the impudence.
Impudence?
Impudence is pretending
to be Fek'lhr
of Klingon.
Your leeway
has run out, Captain.
( roaring )
Your Honor
I appreciate
your indulgence.
Allow me to explain.
A team from
the Enterprise
has taken control of...
this woman's ship
now in orbit
around Ventax II.
Thank you for your
help, Number One.
RIKER:
Glad to be of service, sir.
They have been
monitoring me on
my communicator.
Executing a
prearranged program
on her ship's computer--
a fairly ingenious combination
of force field projection
holography and
transporter effects.
Ardra controls
her "magic"
literally by the
blink of an eye--
centuries-old technology.
An implant which permits
the movements of her eye
to choose and activate
each illusion.
Ardra once told us that she
is known by many names.
Well, at least in that,
she was being honest.
Her crew have admitted
that she is known
by 23 aliases
in this sector
alone.
You had no right.
Deceiving innocent people with
her petty schemes for years.
Ventax II must have offered her
the greatest opportunity
of her nefarious career.
She learned of the myth
of Ardra, studied it
and so expertly played
on your fears
that your people were ready
to virtually surrender to her.
Your Honor,
under the circumstances
I believe it
is only fair
that I release the Ventaxians
from their obligation
and I will let them
keep the peace they have
and I will just be on my way.
With the advocate's
withdrawal
the contract
is hereby dissolved.
This arbitration
is adjourned.
( bangs gavel )
Thank you, Captain Picard.
You saved our lives.
No, Jared, as I've
tried to tell you
you saved your own
lives a long time ago.
Congratulations, sir.
Your Honor.
( tsking )
You would have had
a lot more fun if you'd lost.
Till we meet again,
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Starship Enterprise.
( laughing )