Captain's Log,
Stardate 44502.7.
Early completion of our
mission at Harrakis V
has allowed me to grant extra
personal time
for many of the crew.
This has come
as something of a relief
since our recent
tight scheduling
has prevented the pursuit
of the leisure activities
that are a normal part of life
aboard the Enterprise.
I expect our journey past the
Ngame Nebula to be uneventful
and am personally
using the time
to fulfill a promise
to a colleague.
Dixon Hill around?
He's occupied at
the present moment.
Tell him Gloria's here.
Can't do that.
He doesn't want
to be disturbed.
Tell him it's
Gloria from...
Cleveland.
Doesn't matter
if you're from the moon, hon.
Mr. Hill is incommuni...
incommunica... ca...
...cado.
That's it.
Sorry, hon.
( sighs )
Look, hon,
just tell him
Gloria's here.
Look, when the boss doesn't
want to be disturbed
the boss doesn't want
to be disturbed.
Don't take it personal-like.
I have
an appointment
with Mr. Hill at...
2:00.
It's 2:10.
So? I had a little trouble
getting into the dress.
It took me a little while
to figure out just exactly
what I was supposed
to do with these.
( sighs )
( buzz )
Sorry, Dix.
There's a "lady"
here to see you.
Says her name is...
Gloria.
From Cleveland.
Okay.
He never heard of you.
He's never heard of me?
That's right.
Oh, wait,
I don't think you understand.
You see... this was
all set up in advance,
you see.
I'm supposed to be
Gloria from Cleveland
and I was supposed to be on
Holodeck Number Four at 2:00...
And you don't have any idea
what I'm talking about,
do you?
Not to worry.
Hey, you can't go in there.
MAN:
Get inside.
Close the door.
Who's the doll?
She's, uh...
( with gangster accent ):
The doll's my cousin.
Yeah.
Gloria.
From Cleveland.
I'm sorry about
this... Gloria.
I didn't actually mean
you to get involved.
She knows nothin'
about this, Johnny.
What does...
what does that mean?
Oh, oh, I see.
JOHNNY:
Yeah, right.
What do I look like-- a jamoke?
You ain't nobody's cousin
and you ain't here on a visit.
Now, what do you know
about my money?
Your money?
The money he stole!
You stole his money?
Don't listen
to him, Gloria.
He's lyin'.
Oh... oh!
Oh, Johnny... Johnny!
Talk to me, Johnny.
I'm a great listener.
I'm finished with talking,
sweetheart.
Now I'm going
to get some action
or else!
( machine gun fire )
And this is what
you do for fun.
It's a mystery.
Who is this man?
Who killed him?
Where is the money
he was talking about?
It's... it's a mystery.
Now we have to go
search for clues.
Ah, and that's fun?
That's fun.
( tires squealing )
( people calling out )
( car door slams )
( car departs, tires squeal )
( phone rings )
'48 Packard with whitewalls.
MADELINE:
Dixon Hill,
private investigations.
Damn it, I didn't get
the license plate.
Captain Picard?
Sorry, there's
no Captain Picard here.
Maybe you should try
down at the docks.
There's ships coming in
and out of there every day...
It's all right, Madeline.
I'll take it in here.
Yes, what is it?
Captain,
Lieutenant Commander Data here.
Please excuse
the unusual interruption
but under the circumstances
I thought that patching
communications
through the holodeck program
would be less intrusive.
I appreciate your concern,
Commander Data.
What can I do for you?
Long-range sensors
detect a T-Tauri type star
within a pocket
of the Ngame cloud.
Well, there's nothing
unusual about that.
No, sir.
However, the star's
single planet
falls within the
M-Class range.
It is capable
of supporting life.
Now, that is unusual.
Highly, sir.
Well, thank you, Mr. Data.
Procedure requires
that we investigate.
Recall the Bridge crew
and set in a course.
Aye, sir.
I'm, uh... I'm sorry, Gloria
but there
is a 24th century mystery
I have to investigate.
You are very welcome
to carry on if you like.
No, I've had enough
fun for today.
Entering the T-Tauri
system now, Captain.
Sensors indicate
an energy fluctuation
directly in our path.
Source unknown.
WORF:
Still picking up energy
distortions, but fading.
It seems to be gone.
Wormhole.
Very likely.
Small and extremely
unstable wormholes
have been mapped
near 39 T-Tauri systems
in the last 100
years alone, sir.
Captain, I suggest
we move
to a safer location.
It could reappear
at any moment.
Agreed, Number One.
Ensign, take us on a course...
Captain.
( whooshing rumble )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
DATA:
Captain?
Data.
Careful, Captain.
The stun effect
from the wormhole
was relatively severe.
Apparently so.
For how long were
we unconscious?
Approximately
30 seconds.
I have scanned the entire
ship and detected
no life- threatening
injuries among the crew.
You were not affected?
No, sir.
My positronic system
is immune to the effect.
This is the third
unstable wormhole
I have passed through during
my time with Starfleet.
The first was aboard
the USS Trieste...
Thank you, Mr. Data.
Well, where
the hell are we?
.54 parsecs from
our original position.
Almost a day's travel
in 30 seconds?
Sir, I should realign
the ship's clock
with Starbase 410's
sub-space signal
to adjust
for the time distortion.
Proceed.
Yes, Captain.
Captain, this is Crusher
in Sick Bay.
Go ahead, Doctor.
I'm getting scattered reports
of minor injuries.
What's happened?
The Enterprise just jumped
through a wormhole.
Apparently, we were
all unconscious
for about 30 seconds.
Is everybody all right there?
There's little or no damage
on the Bridge, Doctor.
Acknowledged. Crusher out.
Ship's status?
Reports coming in now.
Nothing serious so far.
La Forge here, Captain.
I've checked impulse engines
and warp drive, sir.
They appear to be unaffected.
Shields and weapon systems
are fully functional.
Counselor,
are you all right?
I think so.
I'm feeling a bit unfocused.
It'll pass.
Well, not too bad,
all things considered.
We're lucky we didn't end up
halfway across the galaxy
into the middle
of next week.
That was never actually
a possibility.
The wormhole's small size
and relatively short period
would make this
a local phenomenon.
There's still
the anomalous
M-Class planet
we were going
to investigate.
Do we go back?
The unpredictability
of the wormhole
would make an investigation
a hazardous one.
A probe launched
from our current position
would be more advisable.
Make it so.
Nothing's broken, Chief
but those ligaments
around the elbow
have been twisted
pretty severely.
What on earth were you
doing when you fell?
Hanging a plant for Keiko.
It's part of a running project
to give me a green thumb.
How's it working?
Everything I touch seems
to turn brown and wither away.
Alyssa,
would you get me...?
Oh, never mind.
I'll get it.
You... don't go away.
This isn't possible.
Alyssa?
Yes, Doctor?
Did you see anyone
near the lab today?
No, I didn't.
You didn't by chance
adjust the environments
on the incubation containers?
I would never touch
one of your experiments
unless you asked me to, Doctor.
Of course not.
I'm sorry, Alyssa.
Thank you.
Probe approaching the
T-Tauri system, Captain.
Readings, Data?
Coming in now, sir.
The probe is
within visual range
of the planet.
On screen.
DATA:
Sensors indicate
a hydrogen-helium composition
with a frozen helium core.
RIKER:
Wait a minute.
Didn't your readings
indicate a Class-M planet
before we passed
through the wormhole, Data?
It is possible
that the sensors
were affected
by interference from the
wormhole, Commander.
It is clearly not
a Class-M planet.
Mr. Data, run a full diagnostic
to make sure that the wormhole
didn't permanently damage
the sensors.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, take us
back on our course...
Captain...
Problem, Number One?
It seems awfully strange
that a malfunctioning sensor
would give such a specific
misreading of a planet.
I would have thought
that a time/space disturbance
would have caused
a lot more confusion than that.
It is conceivable that the
sensors picked up the afterimage
of an actual planet on the other
side of the wormhole.
We could survey the nearby
stars for such a planet.
It would require approximately
six days, sir.
No, no. We don't
have time for that.
We've encountered
a minor mystery.
One that has been solved
to my satisfaction.
Number One, unless there's
a major objection
then Ensign McKnight should
put us back on course
for Evadne IV.
No objection.
Ensign.
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
PICARD:
Come.
I have something
of a minor mystery on my hands.
"A minor mystery--"
that seems to be
a recurring phrase these days.
Oh...
Diomedian scarlet moss.
I didn't know you
were an ethnobotanist.
It's a hobby.
You've got a
good crop here.
As I recall, it's
not easy to cultivate.
That's just it.
I started these spores
right before we were all knocked
unconscious by the wormhole.
You said we were unconscious
for 30 seconds?
Correct.
Then why do these
show a full day's growth?
Perhaps you got some sort
of fast-growth strain here.
Each of these incubators
was set with spores
from completely different
sources in the Diomedian system.
I have a dozen more in the lab.
Perhaps something extraordinary
happened to one of them
but not
to all of them.
Doctor, we were not unconscious
for a whole day.
Everything on board indicates
that we were out
for 30 seconds--
the ship's chronometer,
the computer
everything, Doctor,
including Commander Data.
Jean-Luc, I'm telling you
this is over 24 hours of growth.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Commander Data
continues to maintain
that we were unconscious
for only 30 seconds
despite Dr. Crusher's evidence
to the contrary.
Captain, I have
a hypothesis.
The 22nd century physicist
Pell Underhill
conjectured that a major
disruption in time continuity
could be compensated for by
trillions of counterreactions.
That effect may have allowed
Dr. Crusher's moss
to arrive at the other side
of the wormhole
with the unanticipated growth.
Underhill was talking
about energy.
DATA:
True.
Nevertheless, it is possible
that the phenomenon
could occur in matter
at higher levels
of organization
given the proper conditions.
Thank you, Data.
Intriguing hypothesis.
Well, perhaps
we've got a tempest in
a test tube, after all.
Captain...
Data, I promised Mr. Nelson
that you would assist him
with the sensor diagnostic.
You'll find him hard
at work on deck 36.
As you wish, Captain.
( door opens, closes )
Do you believe him?
I want a frank answer,
Commander.
Not for a second.
I'm amazed
he even proposed it.
What are you
suggesting, Captain?
I'm not sure, Mr. Worf.
I have never known Data
to tell a lie,
and yet...
If we never went
through that wormhole
then what happened to us
during that day?
If we were out
for a whole day
then why didn't
our beards grow?
Whatever it was,
it seems it was something
Data didn't want
to tell us about.
It could be that whatever
caused this situation
also affected Data
and it could be
that he's telling the truth
and that this is all
just a minor mystery.
We could always check
the computer's chronometer.
See if there's any evidence
of tampering.
A transporter
trace analysis
might give us
another indication
of how much time
has actually passed.
Doctor, Commander,
make it so.
Meanwhile, we will
maintain
our present course.
If there is something wrong
with Data
we don't want him
to be aware of our suspicions.
Gentlemen, how
goes the battle?
Long-range and infrared
sensors apparently suffered
no ill effects
as a result of the wormhole.
We are presently
checking neutrino
and heavy particle
detectors.
Great.
I'll take over now, Data.
Captain wants you
back on the Bridge.
See you later
in Ten-Forward?
Nelson, I need your help
with the computer.
Hello, Chief.
How's the elbow?
Oh, much better, thanks.
This isn't
a house call, is it?
No, it's not.
Tell me, do you remember
the last person to use
the transporter
before we went
through the wormhole?
Well, let me check.
Ensign Locklin.
She's one of my technicians.
Tell her to report
to Sick Bay immediately.
CRUSHER:
Electrolyte
concentration?
12.5 deviation from previous.
Interesting.
Check the cellular
membranes.
I'm willing to bet
that the inner turgid
pressure is off
by almost
the same amount.
11.3 deviation from the norm.
Terrific, that's
what I wanted to hear.
Thank you, Ensign Locklin.
That'll be all for now.
Crusher to Captain Picard.
What is it, Doctor?
I need to see you immediately.
I'm on my way to Engineering.
Join me.
Physiologically, each of us
is on a daily cycle.
Our cells have developed rhythms
based on a 24-hour period.
Internal clock.
Exactly.
And I can measure that effect
at the molecular level.
I took a trace
from the last person
to use the transporter
before the incident
and compared her cell function
levels at that time
to what they are right now.
If we were unconscious
for only 30 seconds
those cycles should be
nearly synchronous.
And were they?
No.
We were out for longer
than 30 seconds, Captain.
A lot longer.
I've got some good news
and some bad news.
The good news
is that we were right
about the computer's
chronometer.
There's a security program
to prevent tampering
but it looks now
like it was disabled
and a new program
put in its place.
Someone has reset the clock.
If that's the good news,
what's the bad news?
That Data and I are
the only ones
aboard this ship
capable of doing it.
It is a mystery, Captain.
That is an understatement, Data.
Is it possible
that someone or something
could have affected you
without your knowing?
I am unable to answer
that question, sir.
Data, would you consent
to being examined
by Commander La Forge?
As you wish, Captain.
Will you escort
Commander Data
to Engineering?
I know the way, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
It has become clear that
everyone aboard the Enterprise
has lost an entire day.
As the mystery
of what actually occurred
during those missing hours
continues to deepen
so do my doubts
about Commander Data.
We'll start with
the higher functions
before we get down
to basics, okay?
All right.
Now this won't hurt a bit.
Have you forgotten, Geordi,
that my sensory inputs
are not programmed
to experience pain?
It's a figure of speech, Data--
bedside manner.
You know, I'm just trying
to make you feel comfortable.
I am perfectly
comfortable.
Pattern recognition,
syntactic algorithms
heuristic functions
all normal.
I have noticed, however
that you appear a bit
uncomfortable yourself.
Well, it just seems like
you're not being
completely honest
with us, Data.
I'm your friend.
If there's something wrong,
I want you to tell me.
Maybe I can help.
I cannot tell you anything
beyond what I have
already stated.
Okay.
Excuse us, Counselor?
Mm-hmm.
Captain, I've
finished examining Data.
And?
Nothing's wrong with the
technology that I can see.
He's in perfect condition.
I was almost hoping
that you'd find a problem.
Well, he still could
be malfunctioning
beyond my ability
to detect it.
This entire mystery started
when our sensors
detected that planet.
First, it was Class-M,
now it isn't.
Our sensors
were malfunctioning
but our probe clearly
established
the planet could
not support life.
Data launched that probe.
If he rigged it,
could you prove it?
I could try.
What happened to us
during that missing day?
Surely, there must be
some clues.
Each of us should try and
think of what we were doing
just before we blacked out.
Reenact it if...
Counselor?
PICARD:
Deanna, are you
all right?
Just a moment.
Yes.
Yes, I'm fine.
What happened?
I suddenly became dizzy.
I think I'd better go
to my quarters.
Perhaps the Sick Bay
would be a better idea.
No, no, really,
I'm all right.
Will you see the Counselor
to her quarters?
Aye, sir.
Thank you for coming
with me, Mr. Worf.
You are certain
you are well?
I just need
some rest.
Thanks.
( Troi screams )
Deanna!
Security, override the lock
on Counselor Troi's quarters.
Now!
What's wrong?
The mirror.
I came in here.
I looked into the mirror.
It wasn't me, Worf.
It wasn't me!
It was my face,
but it wasn't me inside.
Is she all right?
I feel fine...
now.
Signs of stress.
Adrenaline by-products
higher than baseline.
But that's a normal reaction
after sudden fright.
All brain functions
check out okay.
What happened,
Deanna?
It wasn't what I saw.
It was... more what I felt.
I looked into the mirror
and it seemed
a stranger
was staring back at me
from behind my own eyes--
as if my face was a mask.
La Forge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Geordi.
I've found something, sir.
I'm on my way.
( door opening )
CRUSHER:
Lieutenant Worf.
Doctor.
Can I help you?
Perhaps not.
Worf, you came in here
for something.
A warrior does not complain
about physical discomfort.
But the Captain
ordered us
to report anything
out of the ordinary.
Are you in pain?
How did this happen?
Do you recognize this planet,
Data?
Yes, sir.
It is the planet our probes
detected in the T-Tauri system.
LA FORGE:
No, it's not.
Actually, it's Tethys III.
I retrieved this image
from the ship's library.
Its geophysical figures
have been slightly altered
but it's definitely Tethys III.
Strange that
an obscure planet
hundreds of light-years
from here
should be picked up
by the probe.
Data
did you take this image
from the ship's library
and program the probe
to send it back to us?
I cannot verify
that hypothesis.
But you don't deny it.
No, sir.
Mr. La Forge, will you
send another probe
to the T-Tauri system.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, Data.
Counselor Troi has just had
a very disturbing hallucination.
Is she all
right, sir?
For the moment.
Can you tell me if Deanna's
incident is related
in any way to this
missing time period?
No, sir, I cannot.
Data, you are the key
to this entire mystery
and you have done nothing
but block my every attempt
to solve it.
Why are you fighting me?
It is not by choice.
What do you mean
by that?
I cannot say.
Would you rather endanger
Deanna, a friend and colleague
than tell me what is going on?
Which would you
place first--
the welfare of a
single individual
or that of the entire crew?
Are you saying
that by not cooperating
you are actually protecting us?
I am not saying that at all.
I merely state a possible
alternative explanation.
Then, Mr. Data, I'm going
to ask you again...
and I order you to
directly answer me.
What really
happened to us?
I cannot answer that.
What would you
have me do, Data?
How would you handle this
if our positions were reversed?
I am apparently guilty
of falsifying
the Enterprise's records
of interfering
with an investigation
of disobeying a direct order
from my commanding officer.
Your duty seems clear, sir.
Do you know what a court-martial
would mean?
Your career in Starfleet
would be finished.
I realize that, sir.
Do you also realize
that you would most likely
be stripped down to your wires
to find out what the hell
has gone wrong?
Yes, sir.
I do.
This wrist has been broken--
broken and reset and treated
with one of our own subcutaneous
bone fusion units.
During the missing day?
That's the only possibility.
Are you suggesting
he was conscious?
I'm suggesting
that maybe we all were.
I certainly didn't repair
a broken wrist
while I was unconscious.
And our memories
of that day?
CRUSHER:
Blocked.
Possibly erased.
By whom?
There are very few individuals
on board
who could have broken my wrist.
Commander Data is
one of those individuals.
I can't accept
that explanation.
Well, he does possess
the speed and the strength.
Granted.
But I'm beginning to suspect
that Commander Data
is refusing to cooperate
because he believes
that he is acting
in the best interests
of the Enterprise.
La Forge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Geordi.
Our probe is approaching
the planet, sir.
Acknowledged.
Maybe now we'll
get some answers.
What do you have,
Mr. La Forge?
Visuals available
now, Captain.
M-Class.
Nickel-iron core.
Nitrogen-oxygen
atmosphere.
The same planet
our sensors picked up
before the so-called wormhole.
Affirmative.
LA FORGE:
No indication
of any space/time
distortion whatsoever.
The probe should
at least be detecting
some residual effect,
even if the wormhole
is inactive.
That's because
there is no wormhole.
There never was.
RIKER:
Sir?
It was a ruse designed
to throw us off the track.
Look at the clues--
Dr. Crusher's
incubation experiment
the computer clock,
the transporter trace--
all indicate the existence
of a missing day.
Lieutenant Worf's
broken wrist
would seem to suggest that...
we were awake
and aware for that day.
Possibly in a struggle
for our lives.
The fact that we're still alive
suggests we might have won.
Not necessarily, Doctor.
Data's behavior would seem
to suggest that we did not.
Why else would he be willing
to sacrifice his career
rather than tell the truth?
If we didn't win,
and we didn't lose...
Then the only
alternative
would be a stalemate.
Maybe a compromise was reached.
A compromise that forced Data
into this silence.
Then maybe by
uncovering all this
we'd run the risk of
upsetting the stalemate.
Maybe we should leave
well-enough alone.
Possibly, Number One,
and I will be prepared
to live with the mystery
but Data's role in this
must be ascertained
or he'll never be trusted
with Starfleet duty again.
Ensign, take us back
to the scene of the crime--
the T-Tauri system.
Warp two.
Within sensor range, Captain.
Drop to impulse, Ensign.
Mr. Worf, maximum shields.
Ready all weapons.
Shields up.
Photon torpedoes armed,
phasers standing by.
( console beeping )
Captain,
an energy field has appeared
between our position
and the planet.
On screen.
Hold position.
Let's see
what it does.
( sensors beeping )
The field has emitted
an energy pulse
approaching the Enterprise.
RIKER:
Too slow to be
a photon torpedo.
It might be a probe.
Let's see what happens
when it hits the shields.
Shields undamaged.
The energy pulse has dispersed.
Counselor Troi...
what is it?
( deep, resonating voice):
The plan has failed.
You have returned.
Your ship is again
in our space.
I was unable
to prevent it.
Nevertheless,
you are here.
The Enterprise is not
a threat to you.
Give me more time.
Our destruction
would only...
Data, Captain wanted me
to bring you to the Bridge.
Counselor?
One moment, if you would.
Do nothing.
It may yet be possible
to salvage the situation.
Reporting as ordered, Captain.
Well, Data, as you can see,
we're back where it all started.
DATA:
We must leave immediately, sir.
Why?
Any further delay
would put us all
at grave risk.
Why?
What is the source
of that risk?
The energy field?
I cannot say.
Data, you sound
as if you're stuck
in a... feedback loop.
You certainly can say.
You have free will.
You have a choice.
My silence is not
by choice, sir.
Not by choice?
Are you somehow controlled
by that force?
Did Geordi miss something
when he examined you?
Geordi's examination
was exemplary.
Then why are you compelled
to disobey my orders?
How...?
During the missing day...
were you contacted by Starfleet?
Did they order you
to conceal the truth from us?
I cannot answer that.
We must leave, sir.
This ship isn't
going anywhere,
not until I get an answer.
Now, who gave you that order?
( door opens )
You did, sir.
I ordered you to lie?
Captain, the energy field
is approaching.
Maintain shields
at full intensity.
DATA:
No, we must vary
shield shape
and strength
as rapidly as possible.
Maximum shields will only
speed the ship's takeover.
Contact imminent.
Do as Data says.
At once.
Aye, sir.
The field is shifting amplitude,
trying to match our shields.
The energy field will eventually
penetrate our shields, sir.
There is no way to counter
the Paxans' technology.
We can delay
their takeover
but we cannot prevent it.
The Paxans?
Who are they?
You have invaded
our system.
DATA:
No.
Worf!
You will only harm
Counselor Troi's body.
PICARD:
We are not invaders.
We are explorers.
Your knowledge of us
is unacceptable.
They are xenophobes, sir--
isolationists.
The Paxans terraformed
a protoplanet in this system
in order to better conceal
their whereabouts.
The apparent wormhole
we experienced
is actually a trap
to keep out invaders.
The energy field
stuns everyone on board
the invading vessel
and then places them in a state
of biochemical stasis.
That explains why
our beards didn't grow.
The Paxans then take the ship
out of their territory.
So the crew wakes up
and thinks
they've been
through a wormhole.
They count their blessings
and keep going?
Precisely.
What went wrong this time?
My positronic brain
is a technology
unknown to the Paxans.
Our stun-field had
no effect on him.
He remained conscious
while we tried to
take over the ship.
When I realized the crew
was incapacitated
I initiated
emergency procedures.
DATA:
Computer, engage Emergency Plan
Zed Zed Alpha.
COMPUTER:
Automatic defense procedures
initiated.
Energy field strength
increasing.
Warning.
Shield penetration 17%.
Computer,
begin random fluctuation
of shield frequency
and modulation.
Executed.
DATA:
With the Enterprise temporarily
protected, I revived the crew.
Computer, release compound ADTH
into the air flow system.
Five parts per million.
Acknowledged.
Initiating compound release now.
( air hissing )
Status, Data?
The energy field is
attempting to match
the shield
frequency, sir.
Options, Mr. Worf?
I do not recommend weapons
at this range, Captain.
Can we go to warp?
Negative, sir.
The field is
also acting
as a tractor beam.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Shields have been penetrated.
All systems
are frozen, Captain.
DATA:
The Paxans can manipulate
energy structures
on many levels.
They took control
of Counselor Troi's body
to communicate with us.
Captain!
( gasps )
( groans )
No, stop, everyone.
Who are you?
( deep, resonate voice ):
You are aware of our existence.
Our attempt to place you in
biochemical stasis has failed.
We have no choice
but to destroy this ship.
If you destroy this ship
then others will come
in search of us.
You may not be able
to stop them all.
Knowledge of your civilization
will be spread
across half the galaxy.
No.
Allow us safe passage
and I will protect
your right to privacy
to the best of my ability.
We will never tell anyone
of your existence.
There are over 1,000 life-forms
on this vessel.
How could you assure
their silence?
This biochemical stasis--
does it suppress
synaptic function?
It does.
Then you have the capability
of affecting memory.
Can you erase
the short-term memory
of everyone on this ship?
Remove all knowledge
of this event?
Allow us to proceed as if
it had never happened?
It would take time.
One of your days.
He is immune to our influence.
Data, I'm going to give
you a most unusual order.
I'm not sure that you will
be able to integrate it
into your program.
As a Starfleet officer
I am required to follow
all of your orders, Captain.
Good...
because our survival
depends on it.
I am ordering you
never to reveal
what has happened
here today--
not to Starfleet,
not to myself even.
You will conceal your knowledge
of the Paxans
for as long
as you exist.
Do you fully
understand, Data?
Completely, sir.
Satisfactory?
Agreed.
Good.
Now, our task
is to eliminate
from the ship's records
any information
that might lead
to knowledge of this incident.
Let's get to work.
We proceeded to erase
all evidence
of our encounter
with the Paxans.
I reset
the computer's chronometer.
And again, the crew
was stunned into
unconsciousness
their short-term
memories erased.
When they were
revived a day later
the computer adjustments
made it appear that only
30 seconds
had passed.
And here we are.
Here we are again.
PAXAN:
Your plan
has failed.
This ship must be destroyed.
No, wait!
The plan failed
because clues were left behind
that suggested a mystery,
and to many humans
a mystery
is irresistible.
It must be solved.
The Doctor's incubation
experiment, Worf's wrist
Troi's hallucinations--
little pieces
of evidence
that suggested
even more clues.
The clock
the transporter trace
Data's odd behavior.
If we eliminate the clues
and begin again...
Again?
Yes.
Consider the first time
a run-through, a rehearsal,
to shake out the flaws.
The second time
will succeed
if we leave no clues.
You are
a most unusual species...
worthy of a second chance.
Proceed.
Deanna?
PICARD:
Welcome back, Counselor.
Geordi, Data, reconfigure
the computer and the records.
Number One, I want you
to oversee the rest of the ship
and this time...
let's get it right.
What happened, Data?
The effect from
the wormhole was
rather intense, sir.
So it would seem.
Everyone but myself was
rendered unconscious.
My positronic system
is immune to the effect.
How long were we out?
30 seconds, sir.
RIKER:
Current position?
.54 parsecs
from our previous position.
Bearing 285 mark 147.
It could be worse.
Yes, sir.
The wormhole appears to have
been a local phenomenon.
Crusher to Bridge.
What happened, Captain?
The Enterprise went
through a wormhole, Doctor.
It seems the entire crew
was unconscious for
approximately 30 seconds.
Is anyone on the Bridge hurt?
Apparently not.
I'll start checking
the other decks.
Crusher out.
Status reports?
Shields and weapon systems
unaffected.
No damage in Engineering.
Counselor?
There's a general feeling
of disorientation on board
but nothing serious,
as far as I can tell.
Very well.
There's still
that anomalous Class-M planet
we were going to investigate.
Ensign, replot a course
to take us back...
Sir, it is likely
the anomalous readings
were the result
of the wormhole's effect.
It was extremely unstable.
I would recommend
against returning.
It might put the Enterprise
at further risk.
We could launch a probe.
That would certainly
be sufficient, sir.
Make it so
and put out a hazard advisory
to Starfleet.
Ensign, set a course
for Evadne IV.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
♪♪