WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Dr. Nesser,
please contact Station 12.
Dr. Nesser, contact...
MAN: Got a Code Blue here.
Call Dr. Berel.
Watch the door.
All right.
Careful, he may have
sustained cranial damage.
WOMAN: Move him to
the diagnostic pad.
Right.
Slowly.
I got it.
Here we go.
Slowly.
That's good.
Need him here stat.
( monitor beeping )
All right, all
right, careful.
Readings?
Uh, they're
fluctuating, sir.
He took a severe blow.
Possible trauma
to the telencephalon.
Start 15 octares
of quadroline.
We'll need a complete
del-scan series.
I can't find
his cardial organ.
What do you mean?
I'm reading
a steady circulation.
There it is.
Up here.
In his digestive tract?
You ever seen
anything like this?
He's missing
three costal struts on one side.
And four on the other.
You think that's something?
Look at this.
He has digits on his terminus.
What are you?
( indistinct voices )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Yes, Doctor.
Right away.
( monitors beeping )
What happened?
You are in the
Crisis Room
at the Sikla
Medical Facility.
You've had a
severe injury,
but you're going
to be all right.
( sighs )
I was caught in the riots
when the police moved in.
That's the last thing
I remember.
Can you tell
us your name?
Rivas.
Rivas Jakara.
Where do you live?
In the Marta community,
on the Southern continent.
You're a long way from home.
Do you have any members
of your family we should notify?
No. I have no family.
I can't stay here.
I have to get...
You're in no condition
to leave... yet.
( groaning )
There are several
unusual things
about your case,
Mr. Jakara.
Your cranial lobes,
for instance.
They seem to be
surgical implants.
I had cosmetic surgery
to correct a genetic
birth defect.
And these?
Another birth defect?
Yes. Isn't
that something?
My father's were the same way.
You want us to believe that
all your abnormalities
are inherited
genetic traits?
I understand
your confusion.
My personal physician
is much more familiar
with these
genetic irregularities.
To be honest,
I would feel much better
back home under her care.
Why don't I talk
to her about that?
What's her name?
Crusher.
Actually...
I'm not sure
you'll be able to reach her.
Why not?
She's taking a sabbatical.
Well, we'll do the
best we can for you.
Oh, there was
one other thing.
We found this
curious-looking device
in your clothes.
What is it?
It's just a toy.
I was taking it
home, as a present.
I thought you didn't
have any family.
It's for a neighbor's child.
Was there anything else found?
I had one piece of jewelry--
a metal pin.
No. I'm sorry.
This was all we found.
( indistinct voices )
( groans )
Genetic
irregularities?
That thing isn't even the
same species as we are.
Keep your voice down.
The last thing we need
is a panic in here
over some--
It's all
the space flights.
They have attracted
creatures from outer space.
That's exactly the kind of
thing I don't want to hear.
What are you going to do?
( sighs )
Of all the medical facilities
available...
why did he have to end up here?
I think we ought to call
Central Security.
Well, I'm not
calling anybody yet.
Not till we've done
a lot more.
A lot more.
I want his story
checked out.
Run a complete search
through the medical library.
Be absolutely certain there's
never been anything like him.
What if there's
more of them, hmm?
They could be everywhere.
Cordon off the wing.
I want security on his
door 29 hours a day
and I want this kept quiet.
WOMAN ( over P.A. ):
Code Three drill in B Wing.
All instructors
report immediately.
Code Three drill in B Wing.
All instructors report...
At 12.4 after launch
the warp field generator
will be activated.
That's when it would
break the light barrier?
Yes, Chancellor.
If we're successful,
the craft will leave
our star system,
and in a matter
of minutes
will be on its way
to the Garth system.
And then what?
And then, Krola,
we'll see what's there.
How long, Mirasta?
We have the prototype
design for the warp engine.
It would simply be a
matter of building
the actual
production units.
If I get your approval
today, ten months.
Maybe less.
KROLA:
Chancellor?
I'll admit
Mirasta's enthusiasm
for her work
is seductive,
but perhaps we're
moving too fast.
Your opponents
will see this
as another example of your
determination to pull us
further from our
traditional ways.
My opponents look back,
as I look forward.
I cannot believe that my people
would choose to retreat
after all we've done.
I agree.
The people were willing
to accept your social reforms
because they believe
in you, Chancellor.
But there are many who say
we have gone far enough.
All these new ideas,
new technology,
and now, space travel?
It confuses them,
frightens them.
I will not allow them
to remain in the Dark Ages.
The warp program will proceed
as you have outlined, Mirasta.
And then we will
slow down, Krola,
to let everyone catch
their breath,
including you.
Mirasta Yale.
Yes?
Please, don't be alarmed
at our appearance.
My name
is Jean-Luc Picard.
This is my associate,
Deanna Troi.
What are you?
We've come with some very
important information.
About what?
PICARD:
About space.
About the universe you
are preparing to enter.
We come from a
federation of planets.
Captain Picard is from
a planet called Earth,
which is over 2,000
light-years from here.
I'm from another planet
called Betazed.
( sighs )
We've been monitoring
your progress
toward warp drive capability.
When a society reaches
your level of technology
and is clearly
about to initiate warp travel,
we feel the time is right
for first contact.
We prefer meeting
like this
rather than a random
confrontation in deep space.
We've come to you first
because you're a leader
in the scientific community.
Scientists generally
accept our arrival
more easily than others.
We almost always encounter
shock and fear
on this sort of mission.
We hope that you will help us
to facilitate
our introduction.
Is this a joke?
Did Lupo and the others from
the lab put you up to this?
Oh, it's certainly no joke.
As you can see,
we are physically
quite different from Malcorians.
And, with your permission,
I'm prepared to prove it to you.
I would like that.
Picard to Enterprise.
Three to beam up.
( conversation and laughter )
It's everything
I ever dreamed of.
When I was a child
my parents would take
me to the planetarium.
And we would sit in the dark,
and it was as if
I was on a spaceship
on my way to another world
to meet people
on other planets.
Part of me keeps waiting
for the lights to come up
and the program to end.
How did you
know about me?
( sighs )
We learn as much as possible
about a planet
before we make
first contact.
One of the things we monitor
are your broadcast signals--
your journalism,
your music, your humor.
Try to understand you
better as a people.
( chuckles )
I hate to think
how you would judge us
based on our popular music
and entertainment.
Indeed.
We do get an
incomplete picture,
which is why we also do...
surface reconnaissance.
You've had people on our planet?
For several years.
PICARD:
These are specialists.
Highly-trained
observation teams--
superficially identical
to yourselves--
and, therefore, able to blend
naturally into your society.
You see, we have discovered
that the most hazardous
aspect of these missions
is the lack
of sufficient information.
You don't have to explain.
I understand.
Although not everybody
on my planet would.
They would think you were trying
to infiltrate our society.
Well, there is
a difficulty here.
One that has forced us
to accelerate
this entire process.
One of our people is missing--
my First Officer,
Commander William Riker.
He was down on the
planet's surface
coordinating with
the observation team
the final details
of contact.
He disappeared.
My people have made inquiries,
but they have not been able
to locate him.
If there is anything
you can do to help...
Oh, of course.
Where was Riker's
last known location?
The capital city.
He was under the name
"Rivas Jakara"--
a tourist
from the Marta community.
Well, we must find him
before someone realizes
what he really is.
If this gets out
prematurely,
it could seriously
complicate matters.
Our ideology is based
on the assumption
that the Malcorian is
a supreme life-form,
and our world
is the center of the universe.
Your arrival will change
our entire understanding
of life.
And some will not
want it to change.
What about Durken?
(chuckles softly)
Durken...
he will be open-minded,
but cautious.
I strongly suggest
that you do not discuss
your surveillance teams with
him, at least not right away.
But with the disappearance
of Commander Riker,
wouldn't it be prudent--
Captain Picard,
I must ask you
to trust me on this.
If you tell the Chancellor
about Commander Riker,
you will undermine everything
that you hope
to accomplish here.
Durken will
assign Krola,
our Minister of Security,
to find him,
and Krola has
his own political agenda.
He will perceive you
as the greatest threat
that our people have ever known.
And he will not hesitate
to use Riker
to prove that he is correct.
( quietly )
...from another planet.
Hundreds of 'em.
I saw them.
It doesn't make sense
that he's the only one.
Think about it.
It's true.
I'm sure they
have a whole...
( whispers continue )
I thought I said this was
to be kept a secret.
You know Nilrem.
Well, it's getting
out of control.
I don't know
what else he is,
but he is still a patient
in this medical facility.
And we have a responsibility
for his care and recovery.
Remind them
of that, will you?
You're not going to be able
to contain this much longer.
I know.
If people get scared enough,
anything could happen.
Mr. Jakara,
we have been unable
to confirm anything
you told us.
No physician named
Crusher is on file--
not on this planet.
( sighs )
Your address in Marta is
an eating establishment.
The cook has never
heard of Rivas Jakara.
Well, obviously, there's been
some misunderstanding.
There's a growing
number of people
on the other side of
that door who believe
that you are not one
of us, Mr. Jakara.
Not one of you?
That you are from
another planet.
Are you,
Mr. Jakara?
Do you realize
what you're saying?
I know how
it sounds.
I'm not anxious
to make a fool of myself.
This new era of space flight...
it fires the imagination.
People see unidentified vessels
in the sky.
They turn out to be
weather balloons.
Well, it's far more likely
that I am a weather balloon
than an alien.
( sighs )
Our medical journals
have documented
several cases of genetic
mutation in recent history.
Some unusual physical
disfigurations
have occurred.
I'm just another case for
your medical journals, then.
Perhaps.
But you, Mr. Jakara,
are hiding something.
And unless you tell me
the truth about yourself,
this rumor will
persist and grow
and could even
become dangerous,
most especially to you.
( door opens )
( door closes )
( ringing )
MAN: Chancellor, Minister Yale
of the Space Bureau
would like to
introduce you to someone.
Call her back, see if the
Vice-Chancellor will do.
MAN: They're out here
waiting to see you, sir.
( sighs )
All right, send them in.
( beeping )
Always time to meet
your friends, Mirasta.
Chancellor, I think
you might want to clear
your afternoon
schedule for this.
And this...
is the Bridge.
Chancellor.
Here we have environment
and engineering stations,
mission operations,
and the two principal
science stations.
Data, allow me
to introduce
Chancellor
Avel Durken
and Space Administrator
Mirasta Yale.
Chancellor. Minister.
Commander Data
is my Second Officer.
He's an android,
Chancellor--
a constructed being.
A machine?
In a manner of speaking.
The term "artificial life-form"
would be more accurate.
Captain Picard,
is there some place
we might speak together
without distraction?
Certainly.
Chancellor,
with your permission,
I would like to "beam"
to the surface.
I have several
matters to attend to.
Not a word to anyone
about this, Mirasta.
Of course.
Mr. Data, will you escort
the Minister
to the Transporter Room?
Chancellor.
Has there still been
no communication
from Commander
Riker, Data?
No, Minister.
He has not returned
to our designated
transport coordinates.
We have continued to scan the
capital city without success.
PICARD: I've been saving
this for a special occasion.
My brother on Earth produces
a fruit known as "grapes"
which he turns into wine.
He's really quite
good at it.
Chancellor,
we have a tradition
called a "toast."
It is a drink
to salute one's friends
and good fortune.
And I would like
to propose a toast
to our new friendship.
( sighs )
We have something
very much like this
on Malcor III.
I think we shall find
we have much in common.
And much that is
not in common.
An opportunity to learn
from one another.
You speak the language of
diplomacy very well, Captain.
It's a language
I appreciate and understand,
but I have learned
to not always trust it.
Trust requires time
and experience.
My world's history has recorded
that conquerors often arrived
with the words,
"We are your friends."
We are not here
as conquerors, Chancellor.
What do you want?
A beginning.
But how we proceed
is entirely up to you.
And if my wishes should
conflict with yours?
There'll be no conflict.
And if I should tell you
to leave
and never return to my world?
We will leave
and never return.
Chancellor,
we are here only to help
guide you into a new era.
I can assure you,
we will not interfere
in the natural development
of your planet.
That is, in fact,
our Prime Directive.
I can infer
from that directive
that you do not intend
to share
all this exceptional
technology with us.
That is not the whole meaning,
but it is part of it.
Is this your way
of maintaining superiority?
Chancellor,
to instantly transform
a society with technology
would be harmful
and it would be destructive.
You're right, of course.
I'm... overwhelmed,
Captain Picard.
I'm...
I'm quite overwhelmed.
I go home each night
to a loving wife,
two beautiful daughters.
We eat the evening meal
together as a family.
I think that's important.
And they always ask me
if I've had a good day.
And how will you answer them
tonight, Chancellor?
I will have to say,
"This morning,
"I was the leader of
the universe as I knew it.
"This afternoon, I am only
a voice in a chorus.
But I think it was a good day."
( grunts )
There are guards out there.
You'll never escape that way.
I'm not afraid of you.
Good.
Because there's nothing
to be afraid of.
We shouldn't fear
the unknown.
We should embrace it.
Can you help me
get out of here?
Are you really an alien?
It's all right
to tell me.
No.
I'm not an alien.
I don't believe you.
You are an alien.
I really have to leave.
I could divert the
guard's attention.
You might stand a chance
if you took the service exit
down the hallway to the right.
To the right?
Fine. Let's do it.
Why should I?
Well...
you know why.
I don't belong here.
I have to get back on my ship...
in space.
I believe you.
Now, will you help me?
If you make love to me.
What?
I've always wanted to
make love with an alien.
Listen, Miss...?
Lanel.
Lanel...
I really have to get going.
All the other... aliens
are waiting for me.
Oh, it's not
so much to ask.
And then
I'll help you escape.
( scoffs )
It's not that easy.
There are differences
in the way that
my people make love.
I can't wait to learn.
But it's...
It's your only way
out of here...
my alien.
Something's happened to him.
I think he's dead.
Go on, get some help.
( whispers )
Okay.
No!
That way.
Thanks.
Hmm.
Will I ever see
you again?
I'll call you
the next time
I pass through
your star system.
( inhales )
MAN ( over P.A. ):
Dermatome analyzer
to third level Trauma Care.
Stop him!
Somebody stop him!
All right, hold it!
He's escaping!
There he goes!
The alien's escaping!
Grab him!
( groans )
Get him!
MAN:
Stop it, all of you!
Stop it now!
Have you all
lost your minds?
Oh! They've aggravated the
injury to his renal organ.
He's bleeding
internally.
Get him into a
surgical cubicle
and call Central
Security.
This has gone
too far.
( murmuring voices )
Their leader, Picard,
has made it clear
that how we proceed is
entirely our own decision.
You cannot possibly
be suggesting
surrender, Chancellor?
They are not hostile.
Mirasta, you are
incredibly naive.
Can you be so enraptured with
the notion of space travelers
that you are blind to the
threat they represent?
I have seen their
vessel, Krola.
If they chose to be hostile,
I do not think
we would be standing here now.
Why should they use force
when we are ready
to lay down in fear?
I do not lay down in fear.
To them or to you, Krola.
Chancellor,
I mean no disrespect,
but I have repeatedly
warned you
about your policies,
taking us too quickly
where we had no business
going in the first place.
New philosophies,
new economics,
new technologies.
And there are still
many people who value
our traditional way of life,
and I, for one,
am willing
to die to defend it.
Open your eyes, Krola.
We are part
of a greater community.
We cannot ignore it.
You would ignore them...
as they infiltrate
and spy on us.
What are you saying, Krola?
We have captured
one of their spies.
Chancellor,
he is Captain Picard's
First Officer--
Commander Riker.
You knew about this, Mirasta?
He has been missing
for two days.
I told Captain Picard
not to discuss this,
because I was afraid this
is exactly what would happen.
What else do you know, Mirasta?
Everything!
They have been on our planet,
observing,
for several years.
Years?
Imagine what they have done--
influenced our young,
stirred up dissent.
They were
collecting information.
Where is this
Commander Riker now?
He's in the Sikla
Medical Facility.
He's recovering
from surgery.
He suffered head injuries
in an escape attempt.
He will recover consciousness
in a few hours.
( quiet voices )
Will he survive?
I didn't think he would
have survived the injuries.
I have to interrogate
him before he dies.
Well, at least give him time
to regain some strength.
Come back tomorrow.
It cannot wait
until tomorrow.
( door opens )
Krola, we can get
help from his ship.
With their medical technology,
he might recover.
We're not giving
him back.
He's the one
advantage we have now.
Use your drugs
to revive him.
Those drugs
increase cardial rate
and vascular pressure.
That's the last thing
we need to do
to him right now.
( whispers )
It will probably be enough
to kill him.
You can't do it.
Revive him.
I'm just a physician,
Minister.
I don't know much
about affairs of state.
But he is a living,
intelligent being.
I don't care if the Chancellor,
himself, calls down here.
I have sworn an oath to
do no harm, and I will not.
Then I'll find someone
to replace you.
( birds chirping )
Chancellor.
You're punctual,
Captain.
I know how
busy you are.
Do you?
I think you know
a great deal more
about me than I know
about you.
In what respect?
You speak
of trust and peace,
and working together
to enter a new era.
And at the same time,
you conduct
secret surveillance
posing as Malcorians.
Commander Riker.
Mirasta said it would be
a mistake to discuss--
Yes.
She has already tried to
accept the responsibility.
It was my error, not hers.
Chancellor,
there is no starship mission
more dangerous than that
of first contact.
We never know what we will face
when we open the door
on a new world--
how we will be greeted,
what exactly the dangers
will be.
Centuries ago,
disastrous contact
with the Klingon Empire
led to decades of war.
And it was decided then
we would do surveillance
before making contact.
It... it was
a controversial decision.
I believe it prevented more
problems than it created.
I can appreciate the logic
of your position, Captain.
But it would seem
that full disclosure
after contact would have
been in order.
In time, there would have been
full disclosure.
I can only ask you
to believe that.
On other worlds,
it would not be an issue.
But here, everything
our observers reported
indicated that the people
of this world
would almost certainly
react negatively to our arrival.
We could see that
even surveillance
might be interpreted as
an act of aggression.
I hoped that we would have
found Commander Riker
before you did,
so that this matter
would not complicate
our introduction.
It was a mistake.
Yes.
A mistake I might have made
in your place.
I rather like it, actually.
Like it?
That you make mistakes,
like any man.
Chancellor, I have made
some fine ones in my time.
Now, I must
ask you.
Will you release my officer?
We'll talk again later,
Captain.
Enterprise,
one to beam up.
Yes, I understand.
I have been relieved
of my duties,
as I'm sure you
already know.
You are Acting Director of
the facility, Nilrem.
Revive him.
Leave us.
I am Minister Krola
of Internal Security.
You are Riker...
an alien.
Yes, we know.
Please bring
my people here.
In time... in time.
But first, I need
to ask you some questions.
Thank you for
seeing me.
If I did not
depend so much
on your expertise
in space matters,
I would have asked
for your resignation.
I felt I was acting
in the best interests
of our people, Chancellor.
When you are selected
to occupy this office,
then you will have the
privilege of deciding
the best
interests of our people.
Picard, I can excuse,
but you, Mirasta.
You should have
trusted me.
Chancellor, we must
release Riker to Picard.
Any hope for a relationship with
these people depends on it.
I can't afford to be
the idealist you are, Mirasta.
But Riker--
I am prepared
to release Riker after
we have interrogated him.
Are you prepared
for him to die, Chancellor?
His injuries are
extremely serious.
A mob at the medical facility
almost killed him.
Krola has ordered drugs
to be used
to revive him for questioning--
drugs that in his condition,
would be dangerous for him.
Without medical aid
from his ship,
I believe that Riker
will not survive the day.
You must tell
Picard where he is.
You have lied since the
moment of your capture,
and I believe
you are lying now, Commander.
No, we're here on a
mission of peace.
Such noble
creatures.
Why do peaceful people
develop such lethal weapons?
Or do you still insist
it's just a toy?
( loud clattering )
An interesting toy,
to be sure.
It is only used for defense.
Perhaps, like
many conquerors,
you believe your goals
to be benevolent.
I cannot.
For however you would describe
your intentions,
you still represent
the end to my way of life.
I cannot permit
that to occur.
Eventually, Durken would choose
to welcome your people
with arms open
and eyes closed.
I must force him
down another path.
When they find us,
I will be dead--
killed by your weapon.
The lines
will be drawn.
A peaceful accord
will no longer be an option.
( whispers )
No...
For my people.
What happened?
He shot him.
The alien shot Krola.
Get me three octares
of adrulmine.
High-frequency
EM charge unit now.
I have a circulation pattern.
It's very weak.
We have to get him
on vital buffers
right now.
I'm a physician.
Don't be frightened.
I need to know
what happened.
Are you doctors?
Yes. He shot him.
With that thing.
Crusher to Picard.
PICARD:
Go ahead, Doctor.
Commander Riker
is near death,
but there's still
some brain activity.
I need to get him
back to the ship.
Acknowledged.
And there's a Malcorian male
with a phaser wound
in his upper chest.
I need to get him back, as well.
We'll meet you
on the Enterprise.
Picard out.
They're both
going to be okay.
We were able to
stabilize Will.
If we had been any later...
Krola?
He was never in
any real danger.
The phaser was on stun.
"Stun"?
It's a defensive weapon.
Have you been able to
ascertain what happened?
Based on the angle of impact,
it suggests
that Krola's left hand was on
the phaser when it went off.
They were struggling
for the weapon.
Commander Riker
was in no position
to offer any kind of struggle,
Chancellor.
Krola was trying
to be a martyr?
Where is this?
You're aboard the starship,
my foolish old friend.
No, Chancellor.
You must not...
You must not pursue
relations with them.
Must not!
I know.
But, Chancellor--
Mirasta...
it goes against every
instinct of my being.
But my people are not ready
to accept what you represent.
Everything that happened in
the hospital proves that.
And Krola
is the best evidence of all.
We must slow down
and allow those who are like him
to join us in the present
before we can move
into the future.
But when we encounter
other beings in space,
our people must be ready.
The warp program
will have to be delayed.
We will divert more resources
to education
and social development,
to prepare for the day
when we are ready.
Chancellor,
I strongly disagree.
( sighing )
I know.
Captain...
you once said if I asked
you to leave,
you would do so
without hesitation.
I'm afraid I must ask you
to do just that.
Well...
it's your decision,
Chancellor.
But I must say...
I regret that I won't have
the opportunity
of knowing your people better.
We're a good people,
Captain--
a society
with much potential.
Once we cross
the threshold of space
we shall have to give up
this self-importance--
this conceit-- that we are
the center of the universe.
But this is not
the time for that.
For now, we will have to enjoy
that sweet innocence.
How will you
keep us secret,
when so many have seen
and heard so much?
The stories will be
told for many years,
I have no doubt...
about the ship that
made contact,
of the alien
who was held prisoner
in the medical facility.
There will be charges
of a government conspiracy.
Some of the witnesses
will tell their tales
and most of the people
will laugh at them,
and go back and watch
the more interesting fiction
of the daily broadcasts.
It will pass.
MIRASTA: I'm sorry to say
he's probably right.
Captain Picard,
I have one last request.
Take me with you.
She will be unhappy
with the restrictions
I must place upon her
at home, Captain.
We may not be back here
in your lifetime.
And... I have to believe
that you cannot be
fully prepared
for the realities
of space travel.
I have been prepared for
the realities of space travel
since I was nine years old and
sitting in a planetarium.
Mr. Worf, to my ready room.
Escort
Chancellor Durken
to the transporter
room, Lieutenant,
and... assign quarters
to Minister Yale.
She will be
remaining on board.
Aye, sir.
Until we return, then.
With luck,
we will both be around
to renew our friendship,
Captain.