Captain's Log,
Stardate 44614.6.
We are approaching Starbase 313
where we will pick up
a shipment
of scientific equipment
for transport to a Federation
outpost in the Guernica system.
During the journey, we will
be hosting a special guest.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
Yes, Mr. La Forge.
It seems that the
exemplary nature
of your work has
caught the attention
of Starfleet Command.
In fact, someone is coming
on board just to see
the engine
modifications
you've made.
Who, Captain?
The Senior Design Engineer
at the Theoretical Propulsion
Group, Dr. Leah Brahms.
Leah is coming here?
( laughing )
Well, this is terrific.
It is?
Well, I mean, I've...
studied her... schematics
for years.
She was responsible
for a lot
of the engine design
on the Enterprise.
Well, it should be
a very enjoyable visit, then.
She'll be transporting on board
as soon as we reach
the starbase.
Would you like to greet
her on our behalf?
I would love to, Captain.
Thank you.
( conversation and laughter )
You keep picking
at that uniform,
you're going
to wear it out.
( chuckles )
I guess I am
a little nervous.
It's, uh...
it's not every day
a man comes face-to-face
with his dream.
What?
Okay, you remember
about a year ago
when we were caught
in that booby trap
the Menthars set?
Mm-hmm.
Okay. While we were trying
to get out of it,
I went down to the holodeck
to study an engine prototype
that was made when the
Enterprise was first designed.
And the computer... well, it
gave me an image of the engine,
but it also created
this hologram of the designer,
Dr. Leah Brahms.
So, you met
a computer-simulated female?
Yeah, but not an ordinary
computer-simulated female.
I mean, she was brilliant,
of course, but...
warm, you know... friendly,
and it was like we worked
as one.
I would start a sentence,
she'd finish it.
What I didn't think of, she did.
It was just...
so comfortable.
Hmm.
Okay, I know it was
just a holographic image,
but the computer was able
to incorporate
personality traits
from her Starfleet record.
You know, Geordi,
everybody falls in love
with a fantasy
every now and then.
No, no, Guinan, see,
you've got it all wrong.
I'm not necessarily expecting
anything romantic here.
It's just, I know,
whatever--
Leah Brahms and I are going
to be good friends.
Dr. Brahms is ready
to transport, sir.
Okay, bring her over.
Hi.
I mean, uh...
Welcome aboard, Dr. Brahms.
I'm Lieutenant Commander
Geordi La Forge,
Chief Engineer.
La Forge.
So, you're the one who's
fouled up my engine designs.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
BRAHMS:
The matter/anti-matter ratio
has been changed.
The mixture isn't as rich
as regulations dictate.
LA FORGE:
Experience has shown me
that too high a ratio
diminishes efficiency.
I worked with the mixture
until I found the right balance.
The magnetic plasma transfer
to the warp field generators
doesn't correspond
to the recommended specs.
Right. Again, I adjusted
the flow.
Sometimes things happen
a little differently in space
than they do
on the drawing board.
Is that a criticism,
Commander?
No, of course not.
It's just a well-known fact.
There's theory
and there's application.
They don't always jibe.
You've charted a completely
new swap-out schedule
for main components
replacement.
You bet.
I found Starfleet estimates
for the MTBF units
to be unrealistic.
I simply determined
my own schedule
based on observation
and experience.
Is that going to be
your only defense, Commander?
That same tired rhetoric?
"Out here in the field,
we learn things
you designers couldn't
possibly understand."
In the first place, Doctor, I'm
not aware of needing any defense
and, in the second place,
if you're determined to be...
Dr. Brahms, you have
an incoming message
on subspace.
I'd like to hear
this message privately.
In my office.
Be my guest.
Thank you.
( console beeping )
Commander, I am picking up
some unusual readings
in the Alpha Omicron system.
At this range,
all I am able to discern
is that it is
an asymmetrical field
of intense energy.
What type of
radiation signature?
Unknown, sir.
The Alpha Omicron system
has yet to be charted.
I recommend
we take this opportunity
for further research.
Well, we're way
ahead of schedule.
Alter course
for Alpha Omicron.
Dr. Brahms, there's no reason
for us to argue.
We're on
the same side here.
I'm aware of that.
So, why don't I take you
on a little tour?
Show you the
adjustments I've made
why I think they work
and we can begin pulling
together on this?
Okay.
And why not start with
the dilithium chamber?
Okay?
Okay.
The anomaly is orbiting
the seventh planet, sir.
It is a mass of plasma energy
contained within
discrete boundaries
by an outer covering
of silicates, actinides
and carbonaceous
chondrites.
On screen.
Magnify.
Is it a ship?
WORF:
It does not conform
to any known design.
Any records of similar phenomena
in Starfleet listings?
No, sir.
This has never been seen before.
Ensign Rager, ahead
one quarter impulse.
Aye, sir.
Put us in orbit of
the seventh planet.
Keep us a relative
distance
of ten kilometers
from the object.
RIKER:
Alert science stations
to stand by.
Tell them to coordinate all
efforts with Commander Data.
Aye, sir.
What happened here?
Who did this?
You remember, the crystal's
been reoriented
to adjust the direction
of the lattice structure.
Remember?
Why would I remember?
Right, why would you?
Uh... well, the ship was
experiencing some difficulty,
and we made this adjustment
hoping that it would work,
and it did.
So, it was your idea?
Not exclusively, no.
It's curious.
This modification
was due to be introduced...
In the next class
starship.
Yes.
How did you know that?
Um... I didn't.
I mean...
Well, it's the next
logical step, right?
Listen, Doctor,
sometimes we have
to fly by the seat
of our pants out here.
So it stands to reason
that once in a while,
we're going to come up with
the same solutions you do.
Listen,
I've got a personnel review
scheduled to start
in about five minutes,
and I know it's been
a long day for you.
So, why don't we get
together later?
Sort of plan out our agenda
for the next day or two.
Agenda?
What it is we want
to accomplish here.
How we might best
go about that.
Maybe even get to know
each other a little bit.
It might
make this easier.
Maybe you're right.
Okay, great.
How about, uh...
my quarters?
1900 hours?
Maybe even have
a bite to eat?
I make a great fungilli.
I love fungilli.
Is that right?
Huh.
Sensors are having difficulty
penetrating the interior.
However, the radiated output
suggests a coherent system
of energy storage
and utilization.
RIKER:
Then it was constructed
by someone?
It is a possibility.
However, the sensor data
gathered thus far
suggests a naturally
occurring phenomenon
with biological
properties.
A life-form?
Yes, Captain.
RIKER:
Mr. Worf,
begin compiling readings
for transmission
to Starfleet Headquarters.
Mr. Data, prepare to launch
three level-5 probes.
Ensign, aft thrusters.
Standard
observational posture.
DATA:
Level-5 probe sequence
ready for launch, Commander.
On your mark.
RIKER:
Stand by, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
What would it be like,
Counselor?
No ship, no bulky space suits.
Just to live between the stars
and have the entire galaxy
as a home.
Captain, we are being probed.
Recommend we raise shields.
Negative, Mr. Worf.
We are curious about it.
It has a perfect right
to be curious about us.
DATA:
Change in readings, sir.
The life-form has increased
its energy output by 50%.
It is moving toward us.
Reverse course, Ensign.
300 kph.
Aye, sir.
Now, easy.
We don't want to alarm
or provoke it.
( rumbling )
( people shouting )
We are caught
in an energy damping field, sir.
Raise shields.
No effect, Captain.
Reverse power, full impulse.
Impulse engines
at full power.
No change in position, sir.
Red Alert!
( alarm blaring )
Mr. La Forge,
prepare to initiate warp drive.
Sorry, Captain.
There's too much interference
to form a warp field.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Radiation levels at 65 millirads
per minute and rising.
Riker to Dr. Crusher.
CRUSHER:
Go ahead, Commander.
All decks prepare
for radiation protocol.
Acknowledged. Crusher out.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Radiation levels at 300
millirads per minute and rising.
Lethal exposure in one minute.
Mr. Worf, ready phasers.
Minimum power.
Ready.
Fire.
Radiation levels dropping back
to normal, Captain.
Energy patterns are
breaking down, sir.
The radiation signature
is no longer stable.
Energy output
is negligible, sir.
Radiation patterns...
no longer coherent.
I believe
it is dead, sir.
We're out here to explore,
to make contact
with other life-forms,
to establish peaceful relations
but not to interfere...
and absolutely not to destroy.
And yet, look
at what we have just done.
Captain, everything you did
was consistent with established
Starfleet procedures.
Number One, you have the Bridge.
Captain, sensors
are picking up
a new energy reading
from the life-form.
Elaborate, Data.
There is a new concentration
of ionizing radiation
growing in the center
of its body.
Then...
perhaps it's still alive.
Okay.
Computer, subdued lighting.
No, that's... that's too much.
I-I don't want it dark.
I want it cozy.
COMPUTER:
Please state your request
in precise candlepower.
See, it's not a matter
of precision, computer.
It's a matter of mood.
Brighter than this.
Hmm. More.
More.
A little more.
Hold! Right there.
Perfect.
Now, some, um, some music.
Maybe, uh...
maybe a little soft jazz.
( music playing )
Mm. No, that's...
that's not right.
Let me think here.
Oh, I got it.
Uh, some Brahms.
A piano étude.
( music playing )
Mm... no, that's, uh...
that's too corny.
Hmm.
Probably everybody
thinks of that.
Computer, just give me
some guitar.
Classical guitar.
Doesn't matter who.
( music playing )
Yes. Thank you.
( door chimes )
( exhales )
Come on in.
Oh, uh... you've changed.
Yeah.
Uniforms are so... formal.
You're less formal than
any Starfleet officer
I've ever met, Commander.
Am I?
I really just wanted to make you
feel more comfortable.
I'm fine, thank you.
I'm sorry.
Come in and, uh, have a seat.
Uh, can I get you a drink?
No, thank you.
You sure?
Mm-hmm.
You know...
your hair... it's, uh...
it's different.
Different than
a few hours ago?
No, I mean it's different
than I expected.
Different from
your Starfleet records.
Oh, yes, I used to wear it up.
Yeah.
Why would you need to see
my personnel files?
Standard procedure
when guests come on board--
protocol.
I mean, it was nothing specific
actually.
Just, you know...
Commander La Forge...
if I seem to be
somewhat unyielding in my views,
it's because I care so very much
about my work.
Oh, I-I know.
To be honest,
people find me... cold,
cerebral, lacking in humor...
But they're wrong.
I assure you.
Well, I try not to be that way,
but when it comes to my designs,
my engines, especially the ones
on the Enterprise...
It's like...
they're your children.
Yes. Exactly.
So, naturally, you're a little
possessive about them.
You understand that?
Yes, I do.
You see...
I feel the same way.
That's amazing.
I don't think anyone has ever...
Sometimes I feel
more comfortable
with engine schematics
than people.
Well, maybe you just haven't
met the right... people.
You hungry?
I'm hungry.
Why don't
I just start dinner, okay?
Commander...
Please, call me Geordi.
I'm sorry.
I hope that I didn't put you
to a lot of trouble,
but I can't stay.
You can't?
I just don't think
that it's appropriate.
Oh, uh-huh.
I'll meet with you
at 0800 tomorrow?
I'm preparing
a list of discrepancies
that I've identified
in your modifications.
I hope--
now that we've reached
an understanding--
that you'll be prepared
to discuss them with me
in a more objective fashion.
Sure. Fine.
Thank you.
Good night, Commander.
Good night.
This new concentration
of energy was detected
only after the surrounding
material became inert.
Could this be some sort
of tissue regeneration?
DATA:
The radiation signature is
similar to the original pattern
but with significant
differences.
Some kind of reaction
to our phaser fire, perhaps?
I believe it is separate
and self-contained
within the body
of the dead life-form.
Another entity.
Yes, sir.
It appears to be
a smaller,
less-developed version
of the original creature.
Huh.
No wonder it attacked us.
It was about to give birth.
PICARD:
Doctor.
It's dangerous to generalize
about new life-forms,
but based on my experience
with other beings
who bear their young
in this manner,
I'd say that the offspring
is still premature.
Otherwise, it would be able
to break through
the outer body shell
of the parent.
Will this creature
be able to survive on its own
without the parent?
There's no way to tell.
We don't have enough information
about the biofunctions
of the adult,
much less the child.
Is there anything
we can do to help?
If we were in Sick Bay,
I'd try a cesarean section.
The first priority
is to free it
from the body of the parent.
We could use our phasers
as a scalpel.
Yes, that might work.
I advise against
this, Captain.
The parent proved to be
a threat to the ship.
We do not know
how the offspring
will react.
Your objection is noted,
Mr. Worf,
but we are directly responsible
for the death of the parent.
We cannot simply wash our hands
of it now.
Doctor, we will proceed
at your discretion.
Good morning.
The first thing
I'd like to do
is inspect the power
transfer conduits.
You realize the only way to
inspect them is to crawl inside.
I designed them, Commander.
I know what's involved.
Here we go.
Power taps-- watch yourself.
The acoustic signature
doesn't sound right.
You're probably the only
other person in the galaxy
who could pick that up.
What's causing it?
It's right up here.
I've never seen anything
like this before.
What is it?
It's a mid-range
phase adjuster.
Puts the plasma
back into phase
after inertial distortion.
This has never
been done before.
I don't even think
this has ever even been
conceived of before.
You should write
a scientific paper.
( chuckling )
Uh-uh, Doctor, no.
Writing is not
one of my strong suits.
But this kind
of refinement
should be shared,
and you deserve
the credit for it.
Well, maybe we could, uh...
collaborate.
Writing is one
of your strong points.
Commander La Forge...
ever since I
came on board
there seems to be something
a little peculiar
about your attitude.
You seem to know
things about me...
even though we've never met.
Well, uh...
( clears throat )
to tell you, uh,
to tell you the truth,
( sighs )
I've studied you.
Your writings,
your Starfleet file.
I've admired you.
You know, your... your work.
Well, I'm flattered, but...
And...
( chuckles ruefully )
Ah...
Well, I really...
I really wanted to meet you
for a long time,
and... I'd like to think
that... we could become friends.
Maybe good friends.
I thought you knew.
I mean, you know
everything else about me.
But, Commander, um...
if I'm hearing
what I think I'm hearing,
then you should know
that I'm married.
( chuckling )
( sighs )
Set phaser power
to three percent, narrow beam.
Three percent.
All right.
Here we go.
The first incision
is complete.
Ideally, the offspring
should now be able
to push through the outer shell
of the parent by itself.
I think it needs
a little more help.
We've done all we can.
I don't want to risk hitting
the offspring by accident.
Come on.
You can do it.
CRUSHER:
Ah! Captain,
I'd like to announce the birth
of a large baby... something.
Well done, Doctor.
Well done.
How could it have been
so far off?
It was based on every
piece of information
on record about Leah Brahms--
okay, with an admitted
margin for error,
but this is an error that's
about a light-year wide.
Not what you hoped for, huh?
Hoped... Guinan,
the woman is about as friendly
as a Circassian Plague Cat.
Only cares
about her work,
hates what I've done
to her engines,
and, to top it all off,
she's married.
The computer never
even told me
she was married.
Computer glitch?
Must have been.
Maybe it was your old VISOR.
What are you
talking about?
Well, the one you wore when you
were on the holodeck with her.
Guinan, it's the same VISOR.
Really?
Oh, I figured it was
probably the one
that lets you see
what you want to see.
( sighs and chuckles )
What's that supposed to mean?
You saw exactly what you wanted
to see on the holodeck.
Sure, the computer made it
look like her,
gave it personality,
but when it came
to the relationship, La Forge,
you... filled in the blanks.
And you had
a perfectly wonderful,
marvelous little fantasy
until the real Leah showed up
and ruined it.
Now, she's probably done
the most horrific thing
one person can do to another...
not live up
to your expectations.
So I'd take a good, long,
hard look at her, La Forge.
See her for who she is,
not for what you want her to be.
( sighs heavily )
DATA:
The life-form's patterns
are stable, Captain.
It seems able to withstand
the solar radiation.
Good. Ensign, set a course
for the Guernica system.
Aye, sir.
We're not staying?
No, Number One.
We've done all
we can to help.
Now it's time
to move on.
This creature can
continue its existence
without any further
interference from us.
It might be wise to put
some distance between us
before we initiate
warp drive.
Very well. 500 kph, Ensign.
Engage.
Captain, it is following us.
Maintaining a distance
of... four kilometers.
Directly astern.
17 degrees to port, Ensign.
Aye, sir.
WORF:
It is turning with us, sir.
Increase to half impulse.
It is matching our velocity.
It's imprinted on us.
It thinks the Enterprise
is its mother.
Change in energy
reading, sir.
I am reading an
internal buildup
of gamma
particles...
Its velocity is increasing.
It is moving directly
toward the ship.
Evasive maneuvers. Full...
Report.
WORF:
Minor damage.
The creature is now
in direct contact
with the hull, sir.
On screen.
Mr. Data?
Sir, the life-form
is draining energy
directly from the
fusion reactors.
It's feeding off the
energy of the Enterprise
as it would
from its mother.
WORF:
What action should we take, sir?
None, Lieutenant.
None at all.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Since the newborn has attached
itself to the hull,
it has been making
greater and greater demands
on the ship's energy,
but we have been able
to stabilize
our power systems temporarily.
How long before the power drain
becomes critical, Mr. La Forge?
If it continues to increase
at the same rate,
six, maybe seven hours.
We may be able
to modify the engine
to extend that
a little longer, Captain.
Your help would be
appreciated, Doctor.
By then, Junior may
not need us anymore.
Mr. Data, is there any way
to determine
what the destination
of the parent
might have been?
I can attempt
to extrapolate
from the heading
it was on when we
encountered it, sir.
Perhaps it was on its way
to provide a safe and supportive
environment for its newborn.
We might be able to deliver it
to the same destination.
Which brings up
the question
of how do we get Junior off
the hull once we get there.
It's almost completely covering
the door of Shuttle Bay Two.
If we open the door
and deactivate the atmospheric
force field...
The pressure
from inside the ship
might push it away
from the hull.
Make it so.
Sir?
Is the appellation "Junior"
to be the life-form's
official name?
No, it is not.
We can save
a lot of energy
just by improving
engine efficiency.
We've run into
similar problems before.
That's actually why I reoriented
the dilithium crystal.
And why you added the
mid-range phase adjusters.
Right.
Commander, it seems
that you've made
a lot more modifications
than I'm aware of.
Do you have a file on
all the work you've done?
Mm-hmm.
It's in the computer.
Good.
Picard to La Forge.
La Forge here.
Commander, I need to see you
on the Bridge.
On my way, Captain.
You go on ahead, Doctor.
Ensign Pavlick can
show you the file
on the engine
modifications.
"Phase coils upgraded
"to 55 field densities.
Plasma inducers interlinked
with generator."
Ensign?
Would there be
any other files
with data on the original
engine specifications?
I believe so, Doctor.
BRAHMS:
This file utilizes
the prototype engine schematic.
It's a holographic program
set in the drafting room
at Utopia Planitia.
I'll run it on Holodeck Three.
Computer, replay program 9140
engine schematic
at Utopia Planitia.
COMPUTER:
Program loaded and ready.
She went where?
Holodeck Three, sir.
I didn't think
there was anything wrong
with her seeing the file.
No, of course not.
Nothing at all!
I'm with you
every day, Geordi.
Every time you look
at this engine,
you're looking at me.
Every time you
touch it, it's me.
( door opening )
Computer, freeze program.
Now... I understand.
No, you don't.
It's not the way this may look.
I called up a replay
of the program file.
I was all ready to compliment
you again, Commander,
for constructing
a program
which contained
the prototype engine.
So that you would always have
a baseline reference
for your modifications.
And now I find
that it's all about...
a fantasy plaything.
It's not like that.
I swear...
I'm outraged by this!
I have been invaded, violated!
How dare you use me like this?
How far did it go anyway?
Was it good for you?
Nothing like that happened.
It was a professional
collaboration.
Oh, I can tell.
"Every time you're touching
the engine,
you're touching me"?
Real professional!
Look, if you watched
the whole program,
you saw what it was.
We were working together
to solve a problem
in a crisis situation.
How do I know how far it went?
How many other programs
did you create?
Perhaps dozens of them,
one for every day of the week.
One for every mood!
All right, look.
Ever since you came on board,
you've been badgering me.
And I've taken it.
I've shown you courtesy
and respect and a hell
of a lot of patience.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Wait a minute.
I've tried to
understand you.
I've tried
to get along with you.
And in return you've accused,
tried and convicted me
without even bothering
to hear my side of it?
So, I'm guilty, okay?
But not of what
you think.
Of something
much worse.
I'm guilty
of reaching out to you,
of hoping we could connect.
I'm guilty
of a terrible crime, Doctor.
I offered you friendship.
WORF:
Captain,
its total volume
has increased by 8.5%
in the last three hours.
I now read it
at 46 million cubic meters.
DATA:
Captain, I have completed
the analysis
of the parent's course
through the system.
It was headed
for an asteroid belt.
Ensign Rager,
set a course
259 mark 318.
Half impulse.
Aye, sir.
Hold a position 500 kilometers
from the periphery
of the asteroid field.
Aye, sir.
Difficulty getting
a clear sensor reading
beyond 4,000 kilometers.
The asteroids contain
large quantities of meklinite
which is interfering
with our scanners.
I am also detecting
traces of Kefnium
a compound found
in the outer shell
of the parent being.
It is likely
the asteroids
provide sustenance
for this life-form, sir.
We could leave the child here.
If Data's right, it would have
an ample supply of food.
Agreed.
Mr. La Forge, are you ready
to separate our guest
from the hull?
Ready, Captain.
Proceed.
( warning Klaxon sounds )
I am deactivating
the atmospheric force field now.
( whoosh of decompression )
Engineering, report.
PAVLICK:
The power drain
just jumped to 93%, sir.
Captain,
the offspring is emitting
high-frequency
radio transmissions.
Is it trying
to communicate?
PAVLICK:
The power drain is increasing.
Approaching auto-shutdown.
Take the engines off-line.
Supplement
with auxiliary power only.
All decks go
to emergency level seven.
Life-support
and critical operations only.
Mr. La Forge, what
is your status?
Sorry, Captain.
The bay has been
completely depressurized,
but... it's still hanging on.
I am detecting other radio
transmissions, Captain.
WORF:
Sensors detect movement
within the asteroid field.
Bearing 257 mark 161.
On screen.
Magnify.
DATA:
At their current speed, sir
the entities will intercept us
in... ten minutes, 31 seconds.
Weapon status?
Auxiliary power only.
Two seconds'
phaser fire available.
Ensign, power readings.
We're on auxiliary generators.
Life-support is
functioning.
That's about all.
Keep your eye on that
generator console.
We've got less than six minutes
to get that baby off our back
before his relatives
get here.
Whatever we try, Junior responds
by sucking up more energy.
Commander
I have a thought...
if you're interested.
Of course.
What is it?
If the baby is nursing,
perhaps what we need
is to find a way
to sour the milk.
If we could contaminate
the energy he's feeding on,
we could try to...
Make it unpalatable
somehow.
Uh-huh.
But the emergency generators
are all we've got.
And how do we modify them
without losing life-support?
Exactly.
Unless...
What?
Well...
this is a space baby, right?
I mean these creatures are born
they live and die
in interstellar space.
Apparently.
Okay.
All matter in space vibrates
in a specific radiation band.
21 centimeters.
Oh...
Oh, that's good, Commander.
That's very good.
If we could alter
the power frequency
so that it's completely foreign
to the life-form's
natural vibrations...
Might just give us enough
to pour a little vinegar
in baby's milk.
Yeah, we have to be careful,
though.
If we upset it this time, we
might lose auxiliary power, too.
If we're gradual enough,
it won't be such a shock.
Hopefully, it'll just
lose interest.
La Forge to Bridge.
PICARD:
Go ahead.
Captain, Dr. Brahms and I
have a plan.
WORF:
Two minutes until the creatures
intercept, Captain.
LA FORGE:
Captain, we're ready down here.
Proceed.
Lowering wavelength
in the energy system...
now.
Reading 18...
15...
13...
11...
eight...
five...
three.
Now at the two-centimeter level.
Any reaction, Bridge?
Negative.
I detect no reduction
in the life-form's
rate of energy
consumption.
One minute, 30 seconds
to intercept.
Not sour enough.
Leah, take it down further.
Reading one...
point eight...
point four...
point two.
I guess it noticed
what we're doing.
The life-form is emitting
its high-frequency transmission.
Energy consumption is rising.
WORF:
Captain,
the creatures are accelerating
their approach.
They are changing color.
Mr. La Forge!
Captain, just
a little more time.
Leah, nudge it down
even further.
Toward .02.
30 seconds to intercept.
BRAHMS:
.08.
.05.
.03.
Now at .02 centimeters.
Auxiliary generators
losing power, Captain.
The entity has disengaged, sir.
Power levels
are returning to
normal, Captain.
Bring the engines on-line
and take us out of here.
RAGER:
Aye, sir.
Mr. La Forge, Dr. Brahms,
congratulations.
You've weaned the baby.
Good work.
You, too.
LA FORGE:
Well, yeah. I-I admit it.
I did get a little attached
to that lady in the holodeck.
The computer never told you
that I was married.
I never asked, see?
And the computer is notorious
for not volunteering
information.
( Leah chuckles )
You know...
I really owe you an apology.
No. No, you don't.
I should have told you
straight out.
Well, if you had, then I
never would have had a chance
to see the look on your face
when you walked in on me...
and me
in the holodeck.
The look on my face?
How about the look
on your face?
I will remember that
for a long, long time.
I wouldn't change a thing.
Except for the way I behaved.
I guess I came here with my own
set of preconceptions about you.
Well, I guess I'm just glad
that I got the opportunity
to get to know you.
The real you.
Me, too.
Worf to La Forge.
There is an incoming message
on subspace for Dr. Brahms.
Acknowledged, Worf.
La Forge out.
My husband.