Captain's Log,
Stardate 44631.2.
We are proceeding
through the rim
of an uncharted
binary star system
where we may have located
the U.S.S. Brattain.
The missing science vessel
failed to arrive
at its destination,
and has not been heard from
since a distress call
29 days ago.
On screen.
Magnify.
RIKER:
That's the Brattain, all right.
The ship
is intact, sir.
with no indication
of structural damage.
Engines?
DATA:
All propulsion
systems are shut down.
The ship
is drifting, sir.
Life-form readings?
DATA:
Inconclusive.
Counselor?
There is life
on board, but...
What is it?
I don't know.
Something...
Number One,
assemble your team.
Dr. Crusher, report
to transporter room three.
Worf. Data.
Commander...
I need to come too.
There is no malfunction
in any of the main systems, sir.
WORF:
Commander.
Here's another one.
This was done
by a phaser
on a setting of
six or seven.
And more over here.
The entire
bridge crew.
Whoever did this
could still be on the ship.
TROI:
There is someone
still alive,
but he didn't kill
these people.
Here.
I think he's Betazoid.
It's all right.
We're going to help you.
( inhales sharply )
Who did this?
Who did this to you?
(Captain Jean-Luc Picard)
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
CRUSHER:
We've almost finished
the autopsies, Captain.
How long will it take
to compile the data?
It's complicated.
The dead were found
all over the ship.
Some were found locked
in their rooms,
barricaded with weapons
piled all around them.
Others were found
in the corridors,
where they'd obviously
had hand-to-hand combat.
It's going
to take some time
to analyze and sort
through the details.
We've identified him
as Andrus Hagan
from Betazed.
Scientific advisor.
He's in a profound
catatonic state.
I'm not getting much, Captain.
A few words,
disconnected phrases.
I can feel his terror,
but I can't seem
to get through to him.
Stay with him,
Counselor.
We're examining the Brattain
for clues, but...
this is the only man left
who knows what happened there.
TROI:
I'm here.
I'm right here.
HAGAN:
Out there...
voices...
Voices?
What do they say?
Both things...
No... no...
Keep talking to me.
I'll try
to understand.
All the engines check out
perfectly, Commander.
Once we get them started,
the Brattain can get back
to starbase
under her own power.
Let's give it
a try.
Pre-heating injectors.
Data, fuel flow?
Matter valves are open
and operating.
Magnetic containment
of antimatter pods
is constant.
Okay, open injectors.
Injectors open.
There is no engine
activity at all, sir.
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
I don't understand it.
( door chimes )
Come.
I've been studying
the autopsy reports.
The conclusion
is appalling.
There was
no outside source,
no alien presence.
All 34 of them appear
to have killed each other.
What could have caused
such an event?
Drugs?
A virus? Poison?
Toxicological tests
showed no unusual substances
in their systems.
And they all appear
to be in good health,
but for whatever reason
they seemed to turn
against each other,
using phasers and knives
and bare hands.
I'd like you
to see this, Captain.
It's from the logs
of the Brattain.
Captain Zaheva's
mental condition
deteriorated steadily
once they had
become stranded.
She began talking
of plots and mutinies.
This was the last
entry in the log,
made after they had been
adrift for over three weeks.
First Officer Brink
and his men were behind it.
They got to the engines.
They don't work
anymore.
Had to eliminate Brink.
The ship is out of...
out of...
We're running out...
too dangerous...
out of Brink...
and his men!
( gasps )
SIGHING VOICE:
Eyes... in the dark...
One moon...
Where are you?
I'm coming,
where are you?
Eyes... in the dark...
One moon...
One moon... circles...
See the eyes...
in the dark...
One moon...
Where are you?
In the dark...
one moon...
( gasps, panting )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44635.8.
Four days have passed,
but we have made
little progress
in solving the mystery
of the Brattain.
I have decided
we should return
to Starbase 220,
and to that end,
Commander La Forge is rigging
the Brattain for towing.
I'm gonna try...
recalibrating
the field generators.
I still don't see
why we can't get
the engine started.
It just...
doesn't make any sense.
( clanging sound )
( clanging sound
growing louder )
Someone's still here.
What did you say,
Ensign?
Can't you hear it?
( clanging sound )
There's someone still alive
on the ship.
( clanging stops )
I heard-- I--
I mean, I...
thought I heard something.
The ship was searched
thoroughly.
There's nobody left
on board.
Sorry, sir, my mistake.
Don't worry about it.
There were 34 people
found dead
on this ship.
That's enough to make
anybody uneasy.
Thank you, sir.
TROI:
I'm here.
Can you hear me?
Tell me about
the voices you hear.
HAGAN:
Bright... bright...
out there...
I don't understand.
Bright what?
Tell me more.
( sighs )
Boy, what a day this was.
I'm doing
an isozyme study
on some populations
of Cardilia,
but they're turning out
to have
these really weird
polymorphisms.
( sighs )
What a headache.
Is that why
you're late?
Oh, no, I had a conference
with Dr. Balthus.
She wants to do a study
on the laticifer ontogeny
of the Kaladian
thorn flower.
But I don't have time
to oversee another project.
Was Tom Corbin
there?
What?
Tom Corbin,
from the science lab.
Remember him?
Of course I remember
him, but--
You use any excuse you can
to pay him a visit.
Miles, what are
you saying?
I think you know exactly
what I'm saying.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say you were jealous.
Do you take me
for a fool?
Hello, Chief.
Having coffee?
No, I'm drinking
too much coffee.
Kind of a surprise
to see you here at this hour.
Yeah, why is that?
You're not out
of the honeymoon yet.
Usually newlyweds
can't keep
their hands off
each other.
She has work to do.
She heads up the plant
biology lab, you know?
Any strange things
going on down there?
Like what?
I've been hearing things.
Kenicki,
in Engineering,
told me he saw a man
in an old Starfleet uniform
riding the lift
near the engine core.
When the lift got to the top,
there was no one on it.
Ghost stories?
There's more.
There's lots more.
There are strange things
happening on this ship, O'Brien.
I'm surprised at you,
Gillespie--
a Starfleet officer?
I have more things
to worry about
than shades
and spirits.
( door chimes )
Come.
Come!
( door chimes )
Yes, yes.
( knocking )
Come?
What..?
Captain, do you have
a moment?
We're concerned.
We're afraid
whatever happened
on the Brattain
may be
starting here.
Explain.
Well, Beverly and I have
been getting unusual reports.
People behaving
strangely.
Others hearing sounds
that aren't there.
Are we talking
about hallucinations?
In some cases, in others
just erratic behavior.
We can't track down any element
that might be responsible.
But everything started
when we found the Brattain.
Yes. Captain,
we have to get
the Enterprise away from here
before it gets any worse.
We're preparing to take
the Brattain in tow.
We'll be on our way
within the hour.
PICARD:
Ensign, maneuver us
into tractor beam range.
Aye, sir.
Is there
a problem, Ensign?
I... can't seem
to remember
how to enter
the coordinates, sir.
Ensign Lin.
Ready now, Captain.
Report to sick bay,
Ensign Rager.
PICARD:
Ready tractor beam,
Mr. Worf.
Captain, thrusters
are losing power.
Impulse engines--
ahead minimum power.
Impulse engines are
not responding, sir.
Geordi, what's going on
down there?
LA FORGE:
I don't know, sir.
Nothing's responding.
Go to warp engines,
factor one.
Engage.
Captain, we don't have
warp drive, either.
We have no functional
propulsion systems?
No, sir.
Apparently,
we do not.
We're adrift.
Just like
the Brattain.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44639.9.
The Enterprise has now been
adrift for a total of ten days.
We have sent subspace
distress calls,
but, because
of our distant location,
we cannot expect a response
for at least another two weeks.
After analyzing
the sensor logs
of the Brattain
and the Enterprise
as well as the data
from the last series
of probes,
I conclude that
we have become trapped
in a massive
rupture in space
into which energy
is absorbed.
You mean
a Tyken's Rift.
A what?
A rare anomaly named
after Bela Tyken,
a Melthusian captain
who first encountered it.
Tyken's Rift.
That would explain why
we don't have engine power.
The ship's energy is
being drained
into the fissure
before we can utilize it.
I was detained.
DATA:
When Tyken was
trapped in the rift,
his analysis determined
that a massive energy release
might overload and dislocate
the anomaly.
Fortunately, his cargo
included anicium and yurium,
which he used to detonate
the explosion.
He then escaped through
the ruptured center of the rift.
But we aren't
carrying anything
that could produce
that kind of an explosion.
Not even our photon torpedoes
would be enough.
Couldn't we replicate
the elements Tyken used?
No, sir, we no longer have
the power to reproduce
complex elements
in the replicator.
We must find a way to generate
a violent energy release
without using
conventional means.
Data, in Tyken's
experience,
did the crew exhibit
behavioral changes?
No. There were no reports of
unusual conduct among the crew.
What about nightmares?
There were no records
of sleep disturbances
of any kind,
Counselor.
Then... what is it?
What's happening to us?
The only one who
doesn't seem affected
by all this is Data.
Bridge.
Number One,
how are...
Sir?
Any hallucinations?
Nightmares?
No...
but I'd be a liar if I said
I felt like myself.
I've had
to bite my tongue
to keep from
snapping at people.
Couple of times,
I've...
gone to my quarters
and felt as if there was
someone else in there, waiting
for me.
I've had
similar feelings.
With everyone
succumbing,
it's even more important
that one of us attempt
to keep control
of his faculties.
I want you to turn in--
take a nap.
I'll be on the bridge.
You can relieve me
in four hours.
Yes, sir.
Deck eight.
No!
Sir?
As you were.
Mr. Data, will you join me
in my ready room?
( snakes hissing )
Commander La Forge
and I have come up with
a potential solution
to our predicament.
Perhaps the modifications
used to increase firepower
against the Borg
would be effective here.
Channeling power
to the main...
um... deflector dish.
Yes, sir. I believe
that within six hours
we could generate
a concentrated
burst of energy which might
disrupt the Tyken's Rift.
Very well.
Proceed.
Mr. Data.
Yes, sir?
It appears
that I am not...
immune to the strange forces
that are at work on this ship.
Yes, sir.
It's a terrifying prospect--
to lose control of one's mind.
When I was young...
I remember watching
my grandfather deteriorate
from a powerful,
intelligent figure
to a frail wisp of a man
who could barely
make his own way home.
Mr. Data, it is
my responsibility...
somehow-- to see that
this ship is guided to safety.
I will need to rely on you
from now on.
We may need to count on you
for our very survival.
I will do
my best, sir.
I'd like to do
more cross-sections
on the brain tissue
of some of these bodies.
Set up the positron
emission sensor in sick bay,
and I'll decide which ones
I want to study.
Yes, Doctor.
( rustling sound )
Go away.
CRUSHER:
Captain, let me
ask you this--
since we located
the Brattain,
can you remember
any of your dreams?
I hardly ever
recall dreams.
Most people don't,
but think--
have you even had a dream
in the last ten days?
I don't recall.
I'm willing to bet
you haven't.
What's more,
neither has anyone else
onboard this ship,
except for Troi.
I began to realize that
when she talked about
having nightmares.
I've done some...
additional
brain tissue scans
on the bodies...
some of the bodies
from the, uh... the...
The Brattain, Doctor.
Right, and I've
also done some scans
on a random cross-section
from our crew.
They both have
the same results--
a unique chemical
imbalance.
Caused by?
Dream deprivation.
Every night,
when we...
we...
enter into...
sleep...
I believe what
the doctor means
is that humans enter into
what is known
as R.E.M. sleep--
rapid eye movement.
It is the level
of brain-wave activity
at which one dreams.
We have to dream
in order to survive.
If we don't reach
R.E.M. sleep,
we don't dream, we...
we begin to lose
our cognitive abilities.
We find it hard
to concentrate.
We forget how to do
the most ordinary task.
Then we become
irritable, paranoid.
Some people experience
hallucinations.
You're describing
the situation on this ship,
but counselor Troi
reported nightmares.
Maybe it's because
she's betazoid.
I don't know why.
All I know is that
there's more going on here
than being caught
in a Tyken's Rift,
and I don't know how
or why it's happening,
but I do know this.
There is an inevitable
conclusion to this pattern,
and if I can't find
a way to stop it,
we will all go insane.
SIGHING VOICE:
Eyes... in the dark.
One moon circles...
Where are you?!
SIGHING VOICE:
Eyes... in the dark.
One moon circles...
TROI:
I'm still here.
I haven't gone anywhere.
Do you remember
anything more?
Double...
double...
What does that mean?
Is something doubled?
Deanna,
nothing's working.
I've tried somatic drugs.
I've tried
inducing theta waves
into the entorhinal cortex.
No matter what I do,
no one can reach
R.E.M. sleep.
No one can dream...
except for you.
Except me...
and all I have
is nightmares.
I can hardly sleep
at all anymore.
In the end,
I'll be like him.
Just like him.
GILLESPIE:
Well, I think it's
some kind of experiment.
See, Captain Picard
is trying to see
how long we'll take it--
stuck here like rats.
Oh, you couldn't be
more wrong.
It's like we're
laboratory animals.
I don't wanna
sit here and wait
for death
to sneak up behind me.
What's that
supposed to mean?
You heard about them
on the Brattain--
shut in their rooms,
dying alone.
That's not for me.
I'd rather
go out fighting.
Okay, all power
has been channeled
to the, um...
the...
The main
deflector dish.
Yes, right,
the deflector dish.
( sighing )
So, uh...
what do we do now?
Data to bridge.
Mr. Worf,
activate the deflector.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Deflector power banks
approaching maximum.
Discharge
in 15 seconds.
Data, this detonation
better work.
We're not going
to last much longer.
Discharge in three seconds.
Two, one.
Nothing.
It just fizzled out.
DATA:
Captain, it appears
the energy output
has been absorbed
into the rift.
PICARD:
Data, can we try again?
No, sir,
if we draw more power
we risk losing
life-support systems.
PICARD:
Understood. Keep me
apprised, Commander.
Lujpu'...
jih'e...
alexandrijn.
Worf, no!
You will not stop me.
Security, Worf's
quarters immediately.
No one can stop me.
Why?
What is it?
I am no longer
a warrior.
I am no longer strong.
I... I feel...
What?
What do you feel?
I feel fear.
To admit that
you are afraid
gives you strength.
Something is
waiting for us.
I am not strong enough
to fight it.
No, Worf.
It's just an illusion.
It's not real.
Please,
put down the knife.
Counselor?
It's all right.
Everything's fine.
Thank you.
Let me take you
to sick bay.
DATA:
Acting Captain's Log,
Stardate 44642.1.
I have assumed command
of the Enterprise
at the request
of Captain Picard.
Our situation is
deteriorating.
Many of the crew
are unable to function,
and our life-support systems
are beginning to falter.
TROI:
Once before,
you said "double."
What did you mean?
What is double?
HAGAN:
Mates...
too bright...
twin... cannot
leave the twin.
One moon circling...
What do you mean?
You can't leave?
No, no.
Please... can't.
You want to leave.
Why can't you?
Can't go.
Help.
One moon...
circling.
Eyes...
that's it...
eyes...
in the dark.
"Eyes in the dark."
That's what the voice said
in my dream.
Is that where
you heard it?
In a dream?
Over and over?
Beverly,
I know what it is.
I know what's happening.
What?
My nightmare.
It's not a dream!
It's not a dream at all,
it's a message.
R.E.M. sleep occurs
at a different frequency
for betazoids than
for other humanoids.
I believe the beings
are using
that frequency to...
communicate
telepathically.
DATA:
It is possible that this
telepathic communication
is creating interference
in the R.E.M. sleep
of other species
That would explain
why the rest of our crew
is not dreaming.
Counselor, what are these...
beings trying to tell us?
They're calling for help.
I think they're trapped,
just like we are.
"Eyes in the dark"
could mean
this twin star system.
Your hypothesis is
certainly plausible.
There may be
another ship...
on the other side
of the fissure
where we cannot
detect it.
Is there a way we could
block their signals?
There is no technology
to block telepathic
transmissions, Doctor.
Maybe communication
through dreams
can work both ways.
I could try
and get them to stop.
Perhaps we could
accomplish more than that.
If there is another ship,
and we can reach them,
we might be able to coordinate
our efforts to free ourselves.
It is conceivable.
When working with patients
with debilitating nightmares,
I've often used
a therapeutic treatment
called directed
dreaming.
Dreamers can learn
to control their dreams,
retain a conscious
memory,
even while
in R.E.M. sleep.
I could remember
a short message
and deliver it to them.
If it were possible,
what would you say?
DATA:
Working together
with the aliens,
we must discover
a means by which
we can produce
an explosion
more intense than
either one of us
could achieve alone.
What is it you're
looking for?
DATA:
These are the elements
we have available.
Some of them could be
used in the creation
of an explosive
reaction.
If we could communicate this
inventory to the other ship,
perhaps they would
be able to--
No, Data, no.
This is too complex.
It has to be a simple,
clear message.
I am uncertain
if a simple transmission
would be adequate.
Stop.
Go back.
Further back...
There. Stop.
"One moon circles."
Yes, Counselor.
One electron
circles one proton.
This is
a hydrogen atom.
"One moon circles."
That's what they've been
telling me,
over and over.
Perhaps the aliens are
thinking as we are--
to collaborate in
producing an explosion.
If hydrogen is combined
with another element--
calendenium, for example--
it is extremely volatile.
But would the message mean
that they have hydrogen
or they want hydrogen?
Well, if it's
a distress call,
I think they'd be asking
for what they need,
not what
they already have.
Then the proper course
of action would be
to release hydrogen
into the rift and hope
they have a substance
that would detonate it.
How do I tell them
what to do?
If you are correct,
Counselor,
I believe they have
already told us what to do
and are waiting
for us to do it.
When we are ready,
the only message
you should attempt
to convey is "now."
I can help keep you
in R.E.M. sleep for a while
with this
cortical scanner.
It will maintain
electrical activity
in your brain
at the proper frequency.
Counselor, you will
have to communicate
with the other ship
within two minutes
of entering
R.E.M. sleep.
TROI:
Two minutes?
Is that all, Data?
Unfortunately, yes.
We have only enough power
to emit a hydrogen stream for
that amount of time.
They must understand
that they will have
to detonate it
immediately.
Captain, we are ready
to implement the plan.
Proceed.
We will have to draw power
from the life-support systems
in order to discharge
the collectors.
This is
Acting Captain Data.
All personnel will report
to the designated
shelter areas immediately.
Life-support systems
will continue
only in emergency shelter areas.
You hear that?
Get us jammed
into shelter areas.
We sit and wait to die.
Nobody'll ever find us.
Relax, Gillespie.
Everybody relax.
Ten forward is
a designated shelter area.
Relax.
Do we want to die here,
like helpless children?
Security to Ten Forward
immediately.
We don't even know
what we're dying for.
Sit down, Gillespie, you're
not helping matters anyhow.
What's wrong with
standing up for ourselves?
MAN:
Yeah.
Picard owes us
some answers.
( beam whirs, sizzles )
What is that?
This is a little souvenir
I picked up from Magus Three.
That was setting
number one.
Anyone wanna see
setting number two?
P.G.O. signals steady.
Visual cortex showing
increased activity.
Rapid eye movements
commencing.
Crusher to bridge.
She's in R.E.M. sleep.
Thank you, Doctor.
Activating
bussard collectors.
SIGHING VOICE:
Eyes... in the dark.
Where are you?
90 seconds remaining.
One moon... circles...
Where are you?
I have to find you!
I have to tell you.
45 seconds remaining.
One moon...
Please...
Circles...
I must find you...
to tell you.
30 seconds remaining.
Ten seconds remaining.
Nothing.
No explosion.
The counselor was
unsuccessful.
Activate
impulse engines.
Engines activated, sir.
We have cleared
the rift, sir.
Warp engines are
coming back online.
Set a course to...
Setting a course
for Starbase 220.
Sir,
as my final duty
as Acting Captain,
I order you to bed.
I shall do the same
for all personnel.
Very well, Mr. Data.
And Mr. Data...
thank you.
Pleasant dreams, sir.