MAN:
Tarchannen Three investigation.
Stardate 40164.7.
Ensign Anthony Brevelle
recording.
Lieutenant Susanna Leijten
in command.
You up and running,
Brevelle?
BREVELLE:
Yes, Lieutenant.
Checked buildings
four and five.
Just like
all the others--
no phaser hits,
no sign of a fight.
Looks like the whole outpost
just vanished.
Lieutenant Leijten,
you'd better come see this.
No footprints,
no vehicle tracks.
The wind probably
erased them, but look...
LEIJTEN:
Freeze visual.
That's Hickman on the right,
Mendez on the left.
And as already noted,
the recording was made
by Ensign Brevelle
five years ago.
Commander Leijten, you said that
before Brevelle deserted
Starbase 112 last week
he'd been ill
for several days.
What about Mendez?
Mendez was seen on the Aries
an hour before she disappeared.
According to witnesses
she seemed completely normal.
And Hickman?
He just passed a routine
physical on Malaya Four
with flying colors.
No, no, no wait a minute.
I know Paul Hickman.
He's a family man.
He's got two kids.
He wouldn't steal a shuttle
and desert.
But Geordi, he was spotted by a
federation supply ship yesterday
on course
to Tarchannen Three.
The original Tarchannen
disappearances
were never solved, were they?
No. We never learned
what happened or why.
49 people gone.
And five years later
the away team
that was investigating
their disappearances
have started
to disappear themselves.
Geordi and I
are the only two left.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Captain's Log,
stardate 44664.5.
We have set a course
to intercept
Lieutenant Hickman's
stolen shuttlecraft
and hopefully to discover
the whereabouts
of the other
missing officers.
And then I almost
married Paul Bogrow.
Bogrow?
Bogrow-- now,
which one was he?
You remember...
the one with
the thin moustache.
Oh, not Bogrow.
I know.
The one who always used
to drive you crazy?
( laughing )
You always thought
he was so full of himself.
Well, I decided that
I'd prejudged him unfairly.
Huh, uh-huh.
And then I decided that
I'd been right
in the first place.
( laughing )
Bogrow...
What about you?
I enjoy the bachelor's
life too much.
That doesn't sound like
my "little brother"
who always wanted advice
on women.
Yeah, obviously,
you were a...
a great adviser.
Well, Suz?
What do you think?
I don't know
but I'm not ashamed to tell you
I'm a little scared, you know?
Yeah, I know.
Well, if anyone's
going to figure this out
it will be the Leijten
and La Forge show, right?
Yeah.
We always made a good team.
A hell of a team.
RIKER:
Commander La Forge,
Commander Leijten,
report to the Bridge.
We have a fix
on the missing shuttle.
On our way, Commander.
Entering the Tarchannen
system, sir.
PICARD:
Slow to impulse power.
Mr. Worf?
Long-range sensors are holding
on the shuttlecraft
bearing 010, mark 271.
Hail the vessel.
Lieutenant Hickman
does not respond, sir.
Put a repeating message
on all subspace channels.
Order the lieutenant
to come about and stand to.
Make it a priority one
communique.
( console beeping )
Still no response, sir.
The craft is now
within visual range.
PICARD:
On screen.
DATA:
The shuttle's acceleration
is increasing.
Its trajectory is moving
directly into
the planet's atmosphere.
He will reach
an atmospheric interface
at an altitude
of 210 kilometers.
If he stays at that speed,
he'll self-destruct.
DATA:
That is correct, Commander.
How soon, Mr. Data?
53 seconds, sir.
Options?
He's out of transporter range.
He's still too far away
to get a positive lock
with the tractor beam,
Captain.
Open a channel.
Open.
Lieutenant Hickman,
listen carefully.
This is Captain Picard
of the Enterprise.
You are in danger.
You must slow your rate
of approach.
The shuttle is approaching
the outer thermosphere, Captain.
He's panicking.
DATA:
At the current
rate of acceleration,
the shuttle will be
destroyed in 28 seconds.
16 seconds to impact.
Lieutenant Hickman,
you must do what I tell you.
Reduce your velocity
and bring your craft
to a positive pitch
of 20 degrees now.
The shuttle is entering
the lower ionosphere, sir.
WORF:
Captain, sensors detect
two more federation shuttlecraft
on the planet surface.
No life signs.
Number One,
prepare your away team.
Worf, Data, Geordi...
I'd like to volunteer
to join you, sir.
Commander.
( distant chirping )
( faint beeping )
RIKER:
Commander Leijten, Geordi,
check out the shuttle.
Data, Worf,
you got the perimeter.
It's the shuttle pod
Mendez stole from the Aries.
Mhm.
No life signs,
Commander.
Sir, I'm certain
we're being watched.
Commander Riker...
found it
in the shuttle.
Where's Commander Leijten?
Riker to Susanna, report.
Fan out.
Let's find her.
Susanna?
La Forge to Leijten.
LEIJTEN:
Over here.
Where have you been?
Mendez and Brevelle
are alive.
You saw the footprints?
Yeah,
but they're not human.
They're here.
Just stand still
and listen.
You can feel it.
They're here.
( beeping )
I'm not picking up
anything.
Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
Susanna?
Stay away.
Suz...
( grunting )
La Forge to Enterprise.
Medical emergency.
Two to Sick Bay.
Do I look as bad as I feel?
You look fine... now.
What happened?
BEVERLY:
Your blood chemistry is way off.
You had a histamine response.
To what, I don't know.
I'm going to run a complete
blood and tissue analysis.
I need to get back
to the surface.
Uh-uh, until I have
some answers
I don't want you
to leave the Enterprise.
I have work to do.
Look, Commander,
you may have just had
an anxiety reaction
down there
but I've got
to know for sure.
It might not be such a bad idea
to take it easy for a while.
I'm not going to stay locked up
on this ship while
the investigation is going on.
PICARD:
Your devotion to duty
is admirable, Commander.
But Dr. Crusher is right.
You'll remain on board
the Enterprise
until we know whether or
not this is connected
with the disappearance
of the others.
Captain...
We have completed our
survey of the surface.
Analyzing all that Data
will keep us busy
for a while.
Yes, sir, I understand.
Data's got a preliminary report
if you're up to it.
Sure, let's get going.
What about La Forge?
I gave him
a complete bioscan.
The results say
he's in perfect shape.
That's what all the reports said
about Mendez and Hickman
before they disappeared.
Captain Picard's wrong.
The way to handle this
is to get back down there
with a dozen away teams.
Fan out from the shuttle.
We can cover a lot
of ground in a hurry.
Use proximity detectors,
infrared sensors...
Susanna...
Oh, Geordi, it's started.
What if what happened
to the others
is happening to me?
You don't know that.
Suz...
I'm here.
And I'm not going to let
anything happen to you, okay?
Okay, come on.
During microscopic examination
of the torn uniform
I discovered
these alien skin cells.
Source?
Undetermined.
Without something else to
cross-reference
it would take us weeks
to try and identify them.
Fortunately,
we have more evidence.
We were able to determine
that these footprints
found near the shuttle
were not made by any known
Tarchannen life-form.
If we're pursuing
the theory
that somehow unknown
aliens were involved
I think I should tell you
that we didn't find
tracks like that
during the original
investigation.
The planet is subject
to frequent sandstorms.
The footprints might
have been obliterated
prior to your
arrival.
Dr. Crusher and I will begin
to search the medical database
in an attempt to match these
with some known life-form.
Aliens or no aliens
why would our people start
returning after five years
to be abducted?
Some sort of compulsion,
like a post-hypnotic command?
Something that happened
while we
were down there the first time?
We can go back
to the mission record
and reconstruct a log
of everyone's movements.
Look for some sort
of commonality--
something we all touched.
Maybe a plant
or the sand.
Or even something
we ingested.
It could even be
in the air itself.
The parameters
are pretty broad, Data.
Any match we make is going
to be inconclusive at best.
I am aware of that, Doctor,
however, I can see
no other reasonable course of
investigation available to us.
We may not have much time.
You're worried about Geordi,
aren't you?
I am an android.
It is not possible
for me...
For you to feel anxiety.
Starfleet personnel
have vanished.
Others may be at risk.
We must do the best we can
to find out why.
( clears throat )
However, I am...
... strongly motivated
to solve this mystery.
MENDEZ:
Ensign Hickman?
( console beeping )
( sighing )
Freeze visual.
We're wasting our time.
That's not how you felt before.
It was your idea to look
for some sort of commonality.
Well, I was wrong.
We're not going
to find anything this way.
We should go back to the planet.
It's all down there--
everything
we need to know.
Well that's just
not an option.
At least not until
Captain Picard says it is.
Computer, resume.
I can't look at that anymore.
Hurts my eyes.
I can't think.
My mind feels like
it's wrapped up in a blanket.
Take a break, alright?
I'll work on this.
I don't need a break.
I need to get off this ship.
Susanna, why don't we go
and see Dr. Crusher.
Forget crusher
and forget your logs.
Tarchannen's down there,
Geordi.
It's waiting for us.
That's where
we should go.
Susanna...
you can't leave.
Susanna!
Geordie.
Her blood pressure
is still falling.
Apply the T-cell stimulator.
We have got to stabilize
her immune system.
She has developed an extreme
sensitivity to light.
We're trying to make her
as comfortable as we can.
Oh, God.
Geordi?
Susanna...
Hold on, okay?
Dr. Crusher will help you.
So just hold on.
It's inside of me, Geordi.
I can't fight it.
It's winning.
Don't give up.
Do you hear me?
You can't give up, Suz.
BEVERLY: This is one of
Susanna's altered skin cells
and this is one of the alien
cells Data found.
They're almost identical.
How do you explain that?
Jean-Luc, I think the people
from Tarchannen Three
who disappeared
weren't abducted.
I think they were transformed
into another species.
Can you stop it, Doctor?
The T-cell stimulator will
slow down the rate of change
but until I find
the cause...
Is the Enterprise at risk?
No. I checked
the cell wall integrity.
Its viability
is extremely low.
I don't think
it's possible
for Susanna
to transmit it.
Then how
did she get it?
I wish I knew.
The only thing
I do know, Geordi
is that it's very possible
that you will be next.
But...
I had two
full bioscans today.
You said I was fine.
I gave Susanna a bioscan too.
I didn't find anything
wrong with her either.
How long?
Brevelle was sick for days
before he left.
Mendez was normal
an hour before she disappeared.
You may have weeks
or very few hours.
Then there's not
much time to waste.
I should get back to work.
Geordi...
Until I know
what we're dealing with
I think you should
stay here in sick bay.
Doctor, you said
that it would help
if you knew
the source of this.
If I could continue my analysis
of the mission records
I might find an answer.
Mr. La Forge...
What if you begin
to change?
What if you feel compelled
to go down to the planet
like the others?
Program the computer
to monitor my movements.
That way, we can be sure
that I don't leave the ship.
What would you do,
Captain?
Would you sit it
out here in sick bay
or try to learn what
it is that's got you--
maybe stop it?
Very well, Mr. La Forge.
You proceed with your
investigation
but I want you to report to
Dr. Crusher for a bioscan
at the start
of the day watch.
Aye, sir.
And Geordi,
if you have symptoms
of any kind
I want to know immediately.
Understood.
One to transport.
I want to make another sweep
of the perimeter.
La Forge, you start
at building four.
Mendez and Brevelle,
begin at two
I'll take five.
All right, computer.
Analyze audio elements
from time index 1447
to 1558.
List all anomalies.
COMPUTER:
No audio anomalies present.
Any subspace projections,
Z-Particle emissions
interferometric frequencies?
No subspace projections present.
No Z-Particle
emissions present.
No interferometric
patterns present.
Damn!
Geordi?
May I inquire how your
investigation is proceeding?
It's not.
Have you attempted
an audio analysis?
Yes, Data
and a spectrographic analysis
and a screen
for ionizing radiation.
I even ran an enhancement
for micro-seismic disturbances.
I've tried it all, okay?
( sighing )
I'm sorry.
There was no need
for an apology.
Perhaps if you indulged
in a brief rest period
you would be able
to approach this problem
with a fresh point of view.
Yeah, you're probably
right, Data
but I've got to keep scanning
these records while I can.
May I assist you?
If I knew
what I was looking for...
really, Data
I think it's just a matter
of me going over it
maybe finding something
I forgot.
I'll let you know if I come
across anything, all right.
All right, computer.
One more time.
OGAWA:
Sorry to disturb you, Doctor.
That's all right.
What's happened?
I thought
you should see this.
Her skin is simulating
the light.
A radiant reaction.
Some sort of mimetic ability?
That's not all.
Her body temperature
is dropping.
It's as if she's generating
a disruptive field.
I can barely get any readings
off of her now.
What's her rate
of transformation?
It's increasing.
That's not possible.
It should have been inhibited
by the T-cell stimulator
unless...
if there's a foreign body
inside her
that's producing these changes--
something like a viral creche...
A very small one
if our scans haven't found it.
I want a full
genetic analysis.
We're going to examine
any abnormality we find
no matter how insignificant
it seems.
One to transport.
Computer, delete the audio.
Wait a minute.
Freeze visual.
Whose shadow is that?
COMPUTER:
Please restate question.
Computer, the shadow
currently displayed
in Section B-3--
what is its source?
Unknown.
Come on, it's got to belong
to somebody.
Computer, replay visual
of the last time index.
No audio and slow to 50%.
Okay, Brevelle's
behind the camera
Susanna and I head off
in that direction.
Mendez moves off that way.
Freeze visual.
Now magnify four times.
And spectrally enhance
those shadows.
Computer, do you have
sufficient data
to compile
a holographic simulation
of this visual record?
A simulation would be limited
to areas scanned
by the visual recording device.
Good, fine.
Scan the entire record
and then recreate it
on Holodeck Three.
Computer, is the Tarchannen
simulation ready?
Affirmative.
Program complete.
Enter when ready.
Computer,
scan Starfleet records
and create a simulation
of Brevelle.
Place him where he was
while recording this.
Okay. Good.
Computer,
based on their
speed and direction
can you extrapolate
each officer's movements
as they walked out
of the recording device's
field of view?
Affirmative, with an increasing
probability of error
reaching 95% after ten seconds.
Understood.
Run simulation.
I want to make another sweep
of the perimeter.
La Forge, you start
at building four.
Mendez and Brevelle,
you begin at two.
I'll take five.
Computer, freeze.
It's all happening too fast.
Computer, reverse simulation.
Run it back to time index 1472.
( reversed speech )
LA FORGE:
Freeze program.
Computer, remove La Forge.
And... now remove Leijten.
And now remove Mendez.
Computer, using vector analysis
identify the source
of this shadow.
There is no object
in the program
which could generate the shadow.
( sighs ) There...
there has to be
something between...
the camera light
and this wall.
Computer,
given the distance
between the light and the wall
can you determine
the most likely shape
and position
of the object
causing this shadow?
There is insufficient data
to reconstruct
the requested object.
( groaning )
All right.
Let's say
that my friend and I here
are about the same size...
say...
1.7 meters.
Now can you extrapolate
its shape
and its position?
Affirmative.
Do it.
( pained gasping )
BEVERLY:
There-- in the thymus.
Some sort of parasite.
It's using
Susanna's immune system
to spread
genetic instructions.
How did it get there?
She could have been infected
during the original mission.
It's small enough to have
entered through any
of the mucous membranes.
But it certainly isn't behaving
like a typical parasite.
It isn't feeding off of her.
It's transforming her DNA
to match its own.
There's not much
of her original DNA left.
And we're going to need
unaltered genes
or we're never
going to get her back.
We've got to get that thing
out of her now.
( machine whirring )
Any luck?
Negative, Commander.
Nothing in our survey
suggests the source
of a parasitic infection.
Crusher to Bridge.
Go ahead, Doctor.
The surgery was successful
but it's going to be
a few more hours
before we know whether
her regenerative systems
are responding.
In the mean time,
we'd better get
Commander La Forge
down here.
PICARD:
Very well, Doctor.
Keep us informed.
Crusher to La Forge.
Computer,
locate Commander La Forge.
Commander La Forge is not
on board the Enterprise.
Bridge, the computer
says Commander La Forge
is no longer on board.
Is that correct?
I am showing
no transporter activity.
All shuttles are secure.
Negative, there is no indication
that he's left the ship.
Computer, what was the last
known location
of Commander La Forge?
Holodeck Three.
BEVERLY: Captain,
if Geordi has transformed
he may be virtually a chameleon.
The skin develops
mimetic capabilities.
He may still be on board,
but undetectable to our sensors.
You search the structure.
I will take the perimeter.
Commander...
Geordi's uniform.
Security,
we have an intruder
in Transporter Room Six...
Captain, the security lockout
on Transporter Room Six
has been broken.
Re-engage now.
I cannot, sir.
The transporter cycle
has already begun.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44668.1.
Dr. Crusher's research
indicates
that we have less than an hour
before Commander La Forge's
transformation
becomes irreversible.
However, all attempts to locate
him on the surface have failed.
I do not read any life signs
on the surface.
Our sensor array
is useless.
We must find some other way
of locating him.
Captain, if we can get
close enough to Geordi,
we can read
his absorption spectrum
with an ultraviolet light.
Can you modify an
emergency beacon
to operate on U.V.?
Yes, sir.
PICARD:
Make it so.
Number One,
as soon as Data is ready
I want you to lead
an away team.
Aye, sir.
( crew murmur )
How long, Data?
I must replace
the emitter module
and reconnect
the power supply.
It will take approximately
two minutes
to complete
the modifications, sir.
Hedrick to Commander Riker.
Go ahead.
I've been able to determine
La Forge's transport
coordinates.
He beamed down
next to the Aries shuttle.
Acknowledged.
He's on foot.
He couldn't have gotten too far.
Let's assume a radius
of ten kilometers.
That still leaves
a search area
of more than 300
square kilometers.
We've got to narrow that down.
What's happening
with the enhanced sensor arrays?
All scans are still negative.
We've got to find a way to
track him.
What about
the high-resolution E.M. scan?
We are adjusting sensors
to read Commander La Forge's
absorption spectrum,
but it will take
several hours.
Geordi doesn't have
I have completed
modifications, Commander.
Excellent.
Dr. Crusher,
meet us in Transporter
Room Six immediately.
He's going to need
a sedative.
Give me ten ccs
of kayolane.
Dr. Crusher...
Say, you look better
than you did an hour ago.
What did you do?
We've removed some kind of
parasite from your thymus.
No, no, no, it's not
a parasite, doctor.
It was their method
of reproduction
to plant a DNA strand
in a living host
that causes a metamorphosis.
Geordi?
He's gone?
Yes.
He's gone back
to the planet?
Try to stay calm.
No but, we have to find him.
An away team is preparing
to search for him.
No, you'll never be able
to find him.
I'm the only one who can.
No you must
turn them off.
The light frightens them.
What about the ultraviolet?
That's beyond their
visual spectrum.
They won't
run away from it.
He could be
several kilometers away by now.
SUSANNA:
No, he's here.
They're all here.
There.
Geordi?
Geordi, stop.
No, wait.
Geordi?
Geordi, my voice
is familiar.
Listen to it.
You can feel
that we share this.
You know
I'm not a threat.
The others--
Mendez, Brevelle--
they don't exist
as humans anymore
but a part of you
still does.
You're not one
of them yet, Geordi.
I can help you
if you'll just trust me.
I know what's going on
inside of you.
The war you're fighting
with yourself.
Your humanity slipping away.
The instinct to run--
it's overpowering,
but they know
how to beat it now, Geordi.
Look at me.
I've come back,
Geordi.
Let me take you back too.
Just take my hand.
Please.
Crusher to Enterprise.
Lock onto
Commander Leijten's signal.
Prepare to beam two
directly to Sick Bay.
We're going home,
Geordi.
Is there no hope
for Brevelle or Mendez?
None.
Susanna...
I'm right here, Geordi
and so are Dr. Crusher
and Captain Picard.
Here's your VISOR,
Geordi.
Lieutenant Commander La Forge
reporting for duty, Captain.
Welcome back, Mr. La Forge.
BEVERLY:
Geordi, this species...
can you communicate
with it?
No.
They act on instinct alone.
In another few minutes,
I wouldn't have...
responded to you, Susanna.
PICARD:
Then we will leave them be.
I'll order warning beacons
placed in orbit
and on the surface.
Hopefully, no one else will have
to go through what you did.
You know, down there, I...
I didn't know who you were
and yet...
somehow...
I believed you.
I trusted you.
That must have
been because of all
the good advice
I used to give you.
Thanks.