You were like
a brother to me.
Do you remember?
We used to play
in the park near the lake.
Yes, of course.
Every summer
you would come to Bergerac.
You used to make swords
out of the reeds.
And when you cut your hand,
you would come running to me
and I would say,
"Let me see."
Oh, how did you do that?
Playing near
the Porte de Nesle.
CRUSHER:
And how many did you
play against?
No more than 100.
Tell me.
No.
( whispering )
Let it go.
What?
( whispering )
Let it go.
Oh!
Let... let it go.
You...
you tell me what
you were going to say.
Do you dare?
CRUSHER:
I do dare.
I love someone.
Ah.
He does not know.
Not yet.
But he is proud, noble,
brave and beautiful.
( wretchedly )
Oh, beautiful.
What's the matter?
With me? Nothing.
It is my hand.
He is in the guards?
Since this morning.
Baron Christian
de Neuvillette
in your own regiment.
Ah.
Promise me...
promise me
to be his friend.
I promise.
Oh, I love you.
I must go now.
Oh, and tell him to write me.
100 men--
what courage!
Oh, but I...
I ha-- I have done
better since.
( polite applause )
Bravo!
Wonderful, wonderful.
Lieutenant Barclay's
performance was adequate,
but clearly not rooted
in the method approach.
I do not understand...
Data, because it's polite.
Good job, Reg.
And only six weeks
for the lessons?
Good job period.
Well, we... we have
a patient teacher.
CRUSHER:
Uh, Worf?
I have an opening
in my workshop.
Well done.
Thank you, Counselor.
You've come
a long way, Reg.
After more...
more rehearsals
than I can count.
I don't just mean
your acting ability.
It takes a great deal
of courage
to put yourself
on display like that.
You... you think...
think so?
There was a time when nothing
could have dragged you
onto a stage
in front of an audience.
You've made
tremendous progress.
I, I... I guess.
Don't you think so?
Well, I just feel
more comfortable...
playing somebody else.
And maybe all of this is...
is... is not any better
than escaping into...
into a Holodeck fantasy.
I disagree.
This isn't fantasy.
It's theater.
You used to withdraw
onto the Holodeck.
You isolated yourself
inside your own imagination,
avoiding contact
with real people.
Look at yourself now.
Look at all the other
people you're with.
You're not just acting,
you're interacting.
Give yourself some credit,
Mr. Barclay.
Maybe you're right.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44704.2:
We have arrived
at the Argus Array,
a remote subspace telescope
at the very edge
of Federation space.
The unmanned structure
mysteriously
stopped relaying its data
nearly two months ago.
The fusion reactors that power
the Array are unstable.
There is a risk
of overload.
What about
the computer systems?
They do not seem to be
functioning at all, sir.
Captain, I am picking up
an unidentified device
1.8 kilometers
from the Array.
On screen.
Magnify.
That's some kind of probe.
I bet that's what
damaged the Array.
Is it emitting
any signals, Lieutenant?
Negative, sir.
I show no activity.
Mr. La Forge,
why not go out
and take a closer look?
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant Barclay,
report to the Main Shuttle Bay.
Enterprise, this is
shuttle five in position.
Ready to begin
a short-range scan.
RIKER:
Proceed, shuttle five.
Reg, why don't we begin
with the passive hi-res series,
all right?
Electromagnetic band?
Give it a try.
I'm picking up
visual wavelengths only,
between 45, uh...
4,500 and 7,000 angstroms.
Let's try
the neutron densitometer.
Nothing.
Hmm... doesn't want to
give up any of its secrets.
Let's go to
an active scan.
No... no modulation.
Really?
You are definitely
not from our neighborhood.
Increase to 3.0.
Commander?
Yeah, Reg?
Thanks for assigning me
to this mission.
Don't mention it.
You're one of
my top engineers.
It's about time you got in on
some of the interesting stuff.
This...
this is why I'm in Starfleet.
There's still no, uh...
no modulation.
Well, hit it with
a positron emission.
Ooh.
What was that?
Computer's down, Reg.
Reg--
Reg?
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
An intense energy surge
from the alien probe
has severely disabled
the shuttle's onboard computer.
The away team
has been transported
directly to Sick Bay,
where Lieutenant Barclay
remains under observation.
Any indication of the probe's
energy source, Data?
No, sir.
Power emissions do not match
any known radiation patterns.
We have not encountered
this technology before, sir.
Very well, isolate the probe
and place it in tow.
We'll take it to Science Station
402 in the Kohlan system.
Captain, the probe
has begun to move.
It is approaching
the Enterprise.
Shields up.
Aye, sir.
There was enough energy
in that flash
to overload
your optic nerves.
It knocked you unconscious.
My visor must have
filtered it out.
Exactly.
But there was no apparent
retinal damage
and the cornea looks fine,
but I'm still waiting
for a full sero-amino readout.
I'll call you
when it comes in.
I'd like this done
as quickly as possible, Ensign.
You shouldn't have to wait
too long for the results.
What do you mean?
Couldn't you use a global mode
in your scanner?
It would be a lot faster.
That's not possible.
We're talking about human cells
here, not isolinear circuits.
I think you'd better stick
to engineering, Lieutenant.
A cell has
an electromagnetic signature
just as a circuit
element does.
Theoretically,
it should work
with just
a few adjustments.
( Klaxons sounding )
I could set it up for you
if you'd like.
Probe now closing
at 15.3 meters per second.
Collision course.
Captain, sensors are reading
no particulate emissions
or subspace distortions.
Then how is it
able to move?
Method of propulsion
is unknown, sir.
Ensign, take us
away from it.
One quarter impulse.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
The probe is matching
our speed and course.
Captain, an energy field
is forming around the devise.
Intensity is 3.2 terawatts
and increasing.
Sir, the shuttlecraft
shield did not provide
sufficient protection
for its computer.
Our computer may also
be vulnerable.
I recommend withdrawal
to a safe distance.
Ensign Anaya, full about.
Half impulse.
One-half impulse.
The probe is following.
Options, Number One?
We can't use
photon torpedoes.
An explosion this close
could cripple us.
Sir, recommend full phasers.
Proceed.
Firing phasers.
No effect, Captain.
The probe's field intensity
is continuing to build, sir.
We are in danger.
Riker to La Forge.
Can you increase phaser power?
Attempting to now, Commander.
Isolate phasers 80 to 120.
Shunt the plasma...
To the emitters.
Yes, sir,
I'm already on it.
Ready.
Phasers are as hot
as we can make them, Captain.
Mr. Worf?
Aye, sir.
Nothing.
Go to warp two.
Aye, sir.
Warp two.
The probe is
still with us, sir.
At warp two?
Yes, sir.
Captain, the probe's
energy output
is overloading our shields.
Failure anticipated
in 47 seconds.
I'm willing
to entertain suggestions.
Captain, we are dropping
to impulse.
Commander, warp power has been
transferred to the shield grid.
Yeah, but by whom?
Barclay?!
What are you doing?
Lieutenant Barclay
to Captain Picard.
You can fire photon torpedoes.
Maximum yield, full spread.
We're too close.
BARCLAY: I'm certain
the shields will hold.
Mr. La Forge?
I don't know
how he did it,
but shield strength has
been increased by 300%.
It should be enough,
Captain.
Mr. Worf, photon torpedoes.
Maximum yield, full spread.
Aye.
Thank you, Mr. Barclay.
You're welcome, Captain.
Barclay out.
I'm sorry if I
overstepped my authority.
Don't mention it.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44705.3:
The Enterprise has destroyed
the alien probe,
but now we are left
with the difficult task
of repairing
the Argus telescope.
Failure to do so
would represent
an incalculable
scientific loss.
Mr. Barclay.
Everyone's still trying to
figure out exactly
how you did it.
It just occurred to me
that I could set up
a frequency harmonic
between the deflector
and the shield grid
using the warp field generator
as a power flow anti-attenuator.
And that, of course, naturally,
created an amplification
of the inherent
energy output.
Uh-huh. I see that.
I'm glad you could join us,
Mr. Barclay.
Your report,
Mr. La Forge.
Each of the telescope's
subspace antenna clusters
is powered by
its own fusion reactor,
but a single computer
controls them all.
So all 18 reactors were affected
when the computer was damaged?
LA FORGE:
Mm-hmm, that's right.
They're starting to overload and
could eventually go critical.
The explosion
would destroy the Array.
And I wouldn't want to be
next door when that happens.
Standard isolation procedure
would be advisable.
I agree. We'll cut off
each reactor from the damage
control system
and repair them one by one.
RIKER: How long will that take?
Two to three weeks at least.
All right, Mr. La Forge...
I don't agree.
We could repair all of
the reactors simultaneous
instead of one by one.
Simultaneously?
All 18?
Yes, sir.
But the Argus computer
is inoperable.
Not entirely.
The core memory
is still intact
and we could program
a completely new control system.
An interesting suggestion,
Lieutenant.
However, that approach
would require much more time
than our original plan,
at least seven weeks.
I could have it ready
for you in two days.
What?
If you could assist me
in the morning, Commander.
Sure, Reg.
The moon--
yes, that will be my home.
My paradise.
I shall find there
all the souls that I love--
Socrates, Galileo.
And when I arrive,
they will question
my worthiness.
What the devil
is he doing there among us?
Philosopher, scientist,
poet, musician, duelist.
Here lies Hercule-Savinien
de Cyrano de Bergerac.
I would not have you weep
any less for that
charming, good,
and handsome Christian.
I only ask this:
that as the great cold
surrounds my bones,
you allow a double meaning
for your mourning veil.
And when you let fall
your tears for him,
some few will be...
for me.
That was a real improvement.
Same time,
day after tomorrow?
Same time.
Reg?
May I join you?
Of course.
Please, sit down, Counselor.
Hard at work?
I'm getting prepared
for tomorrow's meeting
in Engineering.
We're planning
our repair strategy.
I really enjoyed the scene
you just performed.
You're a very
forgiving audience.
Not at all.
I thought you were
brilliant.
You've changed.
Is that
a professional opinion?
Pure observation.
You know, it's true.
I can't explain it.
In the past few days,
I've found confidence
I never knew was there.
I'm proud of you, Reg.
I'm glad for you, too.
Well, I'd better be going.
Must you?
I think so.
Wouldn't you like
to take a walk with me
through the arboretum?
The zalnias
should be in bloom.
Reg, as your
former counselor,
I don't think
it would be appropriate.
I don't need
a counselor.
What I need
is the company
of a charming,
intelligent woman.
Good night, Mr. Barclay.
Where's Lieutenant Barclay?
I stopped by his quarters
on my way over.
He wasn't there.
Computer, location
of Lieutenant Barclay.
COMPUTER: Lieutenant Barclay
is on Holodeck three.
G sub I,
J of T,
as T approaches
infinity...
G of T over G-naught.
So it is, so it is.
I still don't see how
you're going to incorporate
quantum principle
into general relativity
without adjusting
the cosmological constant
a lot more than
you're doing here.
Well, if we increase
the value as you suggest,
we must face
the possibility
of 26 dimensions
instead of ten.
I don't think
I could deal with that.
I certainly could not.
If the semiset curved
into the subatomic...
the infinities might
cancel each other out.
Gruss gott...
they just might.
Ahem.
We had a meeting
at 0700.
I'm sorry, Commander.
Thank you, Professor.
End program.
What was that
all about?
I had some ideas
late last night
and I needed to consult
with the computer about
some quantum electrodynamic
calculations.
A Holodeck Einstein program
seemed like the best way--
I guess I went
a little overboard.
A little?
Most of the stuff
on that blackboard
was way out of my league
and yours, too.
Not really.
I just haven't thought
along those lines before.
It's all really
pretty evident now,
and if you would put
your mind to it, I'm sure--
Reg, ever since our run-in
with that probe,
something's different
about you.
What?
Because I'm beginning to behave
like the rest of the crew?
With confidence
in what I'm doing?
You just spent
the entire night arguing
grand unification theories
with Albert Einstein.
Yes, but...
Reg, something's
happened to you
and we can't
ignore that.
Yes, I've finally
become the person
I've always wanted to be.
Do we have to ask why?
Yeah, I think we do.
Incredible!
The production of
neurotransmitters
in your brain
has jumped by
over 500%.
Pre- and postsynaptic
membranes
have increased
permeability to match it.
I couldn't even guess
at your I.Q. level now.
Probably somewhere
between 1,200 and 1,450.
But that isn't all.
The corpus callosum,
the connecting bridge
between both sides
of the brain,
it is so active now
that the hemispheres
are essentially
behaving as one.
So it's not just
raw intelligence
we're talking about here.
No.
Creativity, resourcefulness,
inspiration, imagination--
they've all been enhanced.
Lieutenant,
you could very well be
the most advanced human being
who has ever lived.
RIKER: Whatever that
alien probe did to him,
Barclay now seems to know more
about the internal workings
of the Enterprise
than anyone else on board.
PICARD:
The question is how are we
going to deal with it?
We could confine him
to his quarters.
How can we do that?
What's he done?
We're talking about locking
a man up for being too smart?
If he's been influenced
by an alien,
wouldn't that
put us all at risk?
Not necessarily.
It might be something as
simple as an allergic reaction
to a bee sting.
PICARD:
Has Mr. Barclay done anything
that could be considered
potentially threatening?
Well, he did make a pass
at me last night.
A good one.
I'd hardly consider
that a threat.
No, but it's unusual
behavior for Barclay.
CRUSHER:
There's something else, Captain.
He taught violin technique
at the music school last night.
I didn't know Barclay
played the violin.
He didn't.
Not until last night.
Look, if we want to save
the Array, we need Barclay--
it's as simple as that.
Until he does
something more menacing,
I see no reason
why we should prevent him
from continuing his work.
LARSON:
Larson to Commander La Forge.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
We're having trouble
containing reactor nine, sir.
It's starting to chain.
LA FORGE: I'm on my way.
You said he made a pass at you,
but you failed to mention
whether he was
successful or not.
Thermal level's up 177%.
Comparable increase
in neutron emissions.
Is the interface between
the computer and Array
still in operation?
Yes, but our computer
is too slow
to direct the repairs.
The parameters are changing
too quickly for it to keep up.
Then we'll have to try
a remote shutdown from here.
Transmitting commands
to the Array now, sir.
Starting close down sequence.
Brower, increase the intake
of liquid helium three
into the reactor wall,
we've got to cool this off.
Transmitting commands.
Thermal level's
increasing, sir.
What happened?
BARCLAY: Unclear!
The interface
isn't fast enough.
LARSON: Commander La Forge,
overload indications
on Argus generator five,
seven and 14.
Damn!
Well, I can't do
anything from here.
I have to find
a better interface.
La Forge to Bridge.
We're looking at a cascade
reactor failure on the Argus.
I don't think we're going to
pull this one out.
Reactor nine
will reach critical
in ten minutes,
43 seconds.
The subsequent explosion
will create a chain reaction
along the entire length
of the Array, sir.
Ensign, stand by for
a jump to warp two.
ENSIGN: Yes, sir.
La Forge,
you've got ten minutes.
Mr. Worf, red alert.
Aye, commander.
( red alert alarms blaring )
Computer, begin new program.
Create as follows:
work station chair.
Now, create a standard
alpha-numeric console
positioned for the left hand.
Now an iconic display console
positioned for
the right hand.
Tie both consoles into the
Enterprise main computer core
utilizing
neural scan interface.
COMPUTER:
There is no such device on file.
No problem.
Here's how you build it.
Argus reactor nine--
28 seconds to critical.
Get us out of here.
Warp two, Ensign.
Yes, sir.
Helm's not responding, sir.
Captain, we have lost
computer control.
What?!
12 seconds to critical.
Go to manual.
I'm attempting that,
sir, but...
There's not enough time.
The computer is
coming back online, sir.
Captain...
the Argus reactors
are shutting down.
We are no longer
in danger, sir.
What happened?
Unknown, sir.
Geordi, what did you do?
It wasn't me, sir.
Computer, how were the Argus
reactors shut down?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
A neural interface was created
to expedite the repairs.
Barclay?
Computer, respond.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I am responding, sir.
I'm sorry if I caused
you any alarm.
It was necessary in order
to secure the Array.
Barclay?!
RIKER:
Barclay, what's going on?
Barclay?!
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Yes, Commander.
It's me.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I'm sorry Captain,
I was only trying to help.
Our computer was too slow
to compensate
for the overload
on the Array,
so I created an interface
that communicated my thoughts
directly to the central
processing unit.
Exactly what does that mean?
My body is as you see it here,
but much of my higher brain
functions and memory
have been transferred to
the starboard computer core.
Mr. Barclay, remove yourself
from the computer system.
Leave the Holodeck.
I'm afraid I can't
do that, sir.
And why not?
My primary cerebral functions
are now operating
almost entirely
from within the computer.
They have expanded
to such a degree
that it would be
impossible to return
to the confines
of my human brain.
Any attempt to do so
would mean my death.
That's it.
I've disconnected
the audio and visual pickups.
We can talk without being
monitored by the computer.
By Barclay.
PICARD:
Report, Mr. La Forge.
It is now almost impossible
to tell where Barclay ends
and the computer begins.
He's actually rewriting
the isolinear chips
each time he extends
himself a little further.
How do we get him
out of there?
We don't.
Not without killing him.
This is an intolerable
situation.
I have no wish to harm him,
but I cannot allow Mr. Barclay
to continue to act
as the computer.
I don't care how smart he is.
Lieutenant Barclay has not
yet extended himself
into the Engineering
subsystems.
It may be possible to
establish an O.D.N. bypass
directly to the Bridge.
But that still won't give us
control of the ship.
No, but it would give us access
to the propulsion systems,
enough to get us
to the next starbase.
How long would it take
to set that up?
A few hours.
Make it so.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Commander La Forge?
Yeah, Reg?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY: I thought
you would be in your quarters.
No, I'm, uh...
just catching up
on some work, you know?
That level three diagnostic
we talked about.
How are you doing?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I wish I could convey to you
what it's like for me now--
what I've become.
Yeah?
Try.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I can conceive almost
infinite possibilities
and can fully explore
each of them in a nanosecond.
I perceive the universe
as a single equation
and it is so simple.
I understand.
You understand?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Everything.
Hmm.
Well, do you understand
how this happened to you?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I believe it is a gift--
that I have been chosen
to fulfill a great purpose.
Uh-huh.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Do you suppose all of this
has changed the way
people think about me?
To tell you the truth, Reg,
we don't know what to think.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I've been concerned about that,
but soon everyone
will understand
what I can do for humanity.
What do you mean?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
We have always perceived
the maximum speed
of the Enterprise
as a function of warp.
But I know now
there are no limits.
We will explore new worlds
that we could never before
have reached in our lifetime.
I will take us to them.
Captain, I am picking up
subspace distortion.
Mr. Data?
This disturbance
is the result
of a highly charged
graviton field emanating
from our warp nacelles.
It is creating a severe bias
in the subspace continuum.
Mr. Barclay,
are you responsible for this
graviton field disturbance?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Yes, sir.
I'm altering subspace
in a way
that's never been
conceived of before.
I'm fairly certain
it will allow us to travel
halfway across
the galaxy in a matter...
Mr. Barclay, I want you to
stop this experiment for now.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY: Captain,
if you'd only allow me...
Mr. Barclay,
this is a direct order.
Discontinue whatever it is
you are doing.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
I really would rather not, sir.
I'm positive that you'll
be pleased with the result
once I finished showing--
Audio is disconnected.
You may speak freely.
How long before the O.D.N.
process is in place?
I have been monitoring
Geordi's progress.
It will be operational
in 17 minutes.
Captain, let me go
to the Holodeck
and try
and talk to him.
Sir, the subspace distortion
continues to increase.
Hello, Deanna.
Reg.
I'm sorry that we can't take
that walk in the arboretum.
So am I.
Reg, you've frightened
all of us.
I'm sure that wasn't
your intent.
Young children are sometimes
frightened of the world.
That doesn't mean
that their parents
should let them stay
in their cribs.
Are we children to you now?
I can see so much more
than you are capable of.
You should trust that.
Deanna, I've always wanted
to earn your respect.
You've got it.
From all of us.
We don't need
any more convincing.
Please, obey
the Captain's orders.
Stop whatever it is
you're doing.
You must trust me.
How can we trust an officer
who doesn't follow orders?
Trust me.
The Captain
will do everything
in his power to stop you.
( red alert sounds )
PICARD:
Picard to La Forge. Status?
Ready, Captain.
PICARD: Proceed.
Acknowledged.
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Commander?
What?
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
You're too late.
Captain, we have not
regained control
of the propulsion systems.
The O.D.N. bypass to
the Bridge has been blocked.
Barclay!
COMPUTER/BARCLAY:
Yes, Commander Riker?
RIKER: Whatever it is
you're doing out there,
you've got to stop it.
WORF:
Sir, we're going in.
Mr. Barclay,
respond at once!
Audio is disconnected.
Lieutenant, take a security
team to Holodeck three.
Disconnect Mr. Barclay
from the computer.
Aye, Captain.
I want you to know,
Lieutenant Worf,
that I understand your duty
in this matter...
Phasers-- maximum setting.
...and that I will in no way
take your actions personally.
Conduits.
La Forge,
initiate stabilization
procedure.
LA FORGE:
Resetting stabilizers
to match subspace flow matrix.
Stand by.
He is protected
by a force field.
We could not
disconnect him.
Mr. Data!
We are experiencing
a quantum level
oscillation delay
doubling in intensity
every 12.3 seconds.
Bio-cellular disruption
is imminent.
Sir!
Where are we, Ensign?
Unless something is wrong
with our sensors, sir,
we're almost 30,000 light years
from where we were.
Center of the galaxy.
Sir, our heading's
been altered.
Approaching
planetary cluster.
Captain, all systems
are back under helm control.
The computer has returned
to normal functioning.
Hmm.
Captain!
Emotive.
Electro-chemical
stimulus-response.
Cranial plate.
Bipedal locomotion.
Endoskeletal.
Contiguous
external integument.
Hmm.
I am Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation Starship
Enterprise.
Hierarchical collective
command structure.
Who are you?
Interrogative.
PICARD:
I am interrogative, yes,
and I would appreciate
an explanation.
I think I can help you
with that, Captain.
Mr. Barclay?
I thought it would be fatal
if you left the Holodeck.
The Cytherians
have reintegrated me, sir.
Cytherians.
The probe was designed
to instruct outsiders
on how to reach
the system.
The technologies are
not always compatible,
they failed
with the Argus computer
and with the computer
on board the shuttle,
but they were able
to reprogram me.
What do you want of us?
The same as you.
Mr. Barclay?
You're both on
the same mission, Captain.
Mission?
Yes, sir.
The Cytherians are exploring
the galaxy just as we are.
The only difference is that
they never leave their home.
They bring others here.
Their only wish--
an exchange of knowledge.
They want to know us.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44721.9:
After ten days in
the company of the Cytherians,
the Enterprise has been safely
returned to Federation space.
We bring back knowledge
of their race
that will take scholars
decades to examine.
Lieutenant Barclay
is apparently no worse
for his experience.
So how much
do you remember?
I remember
doing everything.
I just don't remember
how or why.
How do you feel now?
Smaller.
Just plain old Barclay, huh?
It always seems to come back
to that, doesn't it?
You know, almost everyone
has a moment in their lives
when they exceed
their own limits,
achieve what seems
to be impossible.
The tricky part
is what happens afterwards.
You almost always
feel a sense of loss,
but it is possible to carry
something of that experience
through the rest of your life
in ways that you aren't
even aware of now.
I... I think I know
what you're saying.
Either way, Reg, you're
an important part of this crew.
In fact, I could
really use your help
with that level 3
diagnostic.
Sure.
Excuse me, Commander, but
I believe Mr. Barclay and I
had a date scheduled
for a walk in the arboretum.
The diagnostic can wait.
I'll see you later.
You really don't
have to do that.
I know.
May I?
Checkmate in nine moves.
I didn't know
you played chess.
I don't.