Captain's Log,
Stardate 44741.9.
We have arrived at Tagus Three
where the Enterprise
is to serve as host
for the Federation Archeology
Council's annual symposium.
I look forward to giving
tomorrow's keynote address
with great anticipation.
( door chimes )
Come.
I thought you'd
like to know
the council members
have beamed aboard
and been assigned
their quarters.
Excellent.
Captain, it really
is quite late.
Tell me, Counselor,
with a regard to my lecture,
what do you think will provide
the greater clarity--
a chronological structure,
or the division of each
expedition's findings
into various
religious sociological
and environmental
subgroupings?
I thought you'd
already decided
on a chronological
structure.
There is something
to be said
for a more
scientific approach.
May I make
a suggestion?
By all means.
Relax.
You've written a
brilliant speech.
It will need to be.
Tomorrow, I'm gonna
be addressing
some of the greatest
scientific minds
in the Federation.
Switzer, Klarc-Tarn-Droth,
McFarland--
giants in the field
of archeology.
Compared to them, I'm just
an enthusiastic amateur.
I doubt they see
you as an amateur,
not when it comes
to Tagus Three.
Well, it's true.
I have done my homework.
I have examined
the findings
of every archeological
expedition conducted
on the planet's surface.
It is unfortunate
that the Taguans
no longer allow outsiders
to visit the ruins.
Indeed. Especially
since we know
so little about
their origins.
But I think... I think
that I have constructed
some plausible
theories of my own.
And I'm sure the council
members will agree with you.
Your support is
appreciated, Counselor.
Now, good night, Captain.
VASH:
Bring back any memories?
Vash!
How did you get in here?
I came in through the window.
( relic falling )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I had no idea you were a member
of the Archeology Council.
You are a member...
aren't you?
More or less.
Why did you come
to Tagus Three?
To see you, of course.
Is that the
only reason?
Isn't it enough?
I wish I could
believe you.
( sighs )
I really have missed you,
Jean-Luc.
( door chimes )
Excuse me.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Oh!
Excuse me.
I didn't realize
you had company.
Uh, that's all right.
Allow me to introduce you.
This is Beverly.
Dr. Beverly...
Doctor-- Dr. Beverly Crusher.
This is, um... Vash.
She's a friend of mine from
the Archeology Council.
I didn't mean
to interrupt.
The Captain and I often
share morning tea together.
VASH:
Yes, I know.
Jean-Luc has told me
all about you.
Really?
When was that?
On Risa,
where we met.
I see.
Well, that must have been
during your vacation last year.
No-- yes.
Yes.
BEVERLY:
Well, I am surprised
he didn't mention you.
So am I.
Doctor, are you busy?
Not at the moment.
I was wondering,
I would love to see
some more of this
marvelous ship.
I would be delighted
to show it to you.
I, um...
That is, if it's all right
with you, Jean-Luc.
Of course.
Don't worry.
I promise to behave myself.
And this is Ten Forward,
where the council's welcoming
reception will be held today.
Well, I can't think
of a better location.
Tell me, does Jean-Luc
come here often?
BEVERLY:
Not often.
The Captain is a
very private man.
Would you like
something to drink?
Please.
Eternity never
looked so lovely.
Excuse me?
I was referring
to the view-- eternity.
It never looked so lovely.
You must be Commander Riker.
I'm afraid you have me
at a disadvantage.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
I believe you were
about to tell me that...
my eyes are as mysterious
as the stars.
You're a Betazoid.
( chuckles )
Not at all.
It's just that Jean-Luc does
a very good imitation of you.
He does?
Mmm.
I see you two have met.
Not exactly.
This is Vash, a member
of the Archeology Council,
and a friend of
the Captain's.
So I gathered.
They met during
his visit to Risa.
On Risa?
That vacation must have
been better than he let on.
You mean, he never mentioned me
to you either?
MAN: Dr. Crusher,
please report to Sick Bay.
I'm afraid I won't be
able to finish our tour.
But perhaps Commander Riker
could take over for me.
It would be
my pleasure.
This is the Main Bridge,
the command center
of the Enterprise,
and our last stop.
Vash, Commander La Forge.
Vash, hello.
Hello.
Commander Data.
How do you do?
And this is
Lieutenant Worf.
Hello.
Something wrong,
Lieutenant?
I had not been informed
that council members
had been granted
Bridge clearance.
Well, I think we can make
an exception in this case.
Vash is a guest
of the captain.
Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
Is this where
Jean-Luc sits?
RIKER:
That's the big chair.
Mm-hmm.
Well, I can see
where being
a starship captain
has its rewards.
I'm glad that you approve.
I suppose I'll go
back to my room now
and get ready for
the reception.
By all means.
Well, I suppose I'll
see you then, then.
I look forward to it.
Fascinating woman.
I don't understand.
I thought being
the ship's counselor
meant the captain
confided in you.
He does when he
thinks it's necessary.
And he never spoke
to you about me?
Not that I recall.
Not even a hint?
You must understand,
the captain is a very...
private man.
Private man.
I know.
Excuse me.
Of course.
Nice legs...
for a human.
But, unfortunately...
Jean-Luc,
we need to talk.
Excuse me.
Well, the reception
seems to be going well.
Forget the reception
for a moment.
Why have you never mentioned
me to your friends?
What would you
have me tell them?
That we met,
for one thing.
That we had an adventure
together, some fun.
It wouldn't be possible.
Why not?
It would be, uh...
inappropriate.
I wasn't expecting you to
go into intimate details.
A captain
does not reveal
his personal feelings
to his crew.
Is that a Starfleet
regulation,
or did you just
make that up yourself?
I'm sorry
if you're upset.
And I'm sorry if my being
here embarrasses you.
How was the reception?
Splendid.
Jean-Luc, it's wonderful
to see you again.
How about a big hug?
Well don't just stand
there, say something.
Get out of my chair!
Aww.
And I was hoping for something
more along the lines of,
"Welcome back, Q.
It's a pleasure to see
you again, my old friend."
We're not friends.
You wound me,
mon capitaine.
There.
Perhaps now, your manners
will show some improvement.
What brings you here, Q?
Have you been banished by
the Continuum once again?
Oh, hardly.
They're still apologizing
to me for the last time.
Then what is it you want?
Do I always have to
have a reason to stop by?
I was merely in the sector.
I was, uh...
( chuckles )
You force a confession from me.
The truth is,
I have a debt to repay.
A debt?
To you.
And it gnaws at me, and it
interferes with each of my days.
I have no idea what you're
talking about.
Without your assistance
on our last encounter,
I would never have survived.
I would have taken my own life
but for you.
We all make mistakes.
Your good deed made possible
my reinstatement
in the Continuum,
and I resent
owing you anything.
So, I'm here
to pay up.
Tell me, what is it you wish,
and I'll be gone.
Just be gone.
That'll do nicely.
No, no, no, no, no,
it has to be something
more-- more, uh...
constructive.
That's my new
word for the day.
Some other time, Q.
Right now, I have other
matters to attend to.
Yes, your speech.
I read it.
It's dull, plodding,
pedantic-- much like yourself.
I could help you
with it.
No, thank you.
You've never actually
been to the ruins
of Tagus Three, have you?
No, they were sealed off
more than a century ago.
Well, that explains it then.
How can you write
about something
that you've never seen?
I know.
Why don't I take you there?
Out of the question.
That would mean
breaking Taguan law.
Must you always be so ethical?
I suppose we could travel
back in time.
You could see what Tagus
was like two billion years ago.
They really knew how to party
back in those days.
My answer is still no.
My lecture will have
to stand on its own.
And now, will you
please leave my ship?!
You are simply the most
impossible person
to buy a gift for.
Commander Riker, will you
report to my ready room?
Yes, Captain?
I've just been paid
a visit from Q.
Q?
Any idea what he's up to?
He wants to do something
nice for me.
I'll alert the crew.
Captain.
( door chimes )
VASH:
Who's there?
It's me.
Who?
Jean-Luc.
Yes?
May I come in?
Let me try to explain.
I... I am by no means
embarrassed by
your presence here.
On the contrary.
What's this--
a map of the ruins?
( sighs )
I thought that I was the only
reason you came to Tagus.
I never fooled
you for a second.
Still, you are the most
important reason.
Am I?
That's the problem with being
such a well-known liar--
even when I'm telling the
truth, no one believes me.
This equipment will have
to be confiscated.
Is that necessary?
If the Taguans were to
catch you down there...
Oh, come on.
You gave me the same warning
about Sarathong Five.
I remember.
Well, it didn't stop me
from going there.
I brought back some very
impressive artifacts too.
Which no doubt you sold
for a very impressive profit.
That's what I do.
Not on board my ship.
I will not allow it.
Let's get one thing
straight though, Picard.
I cannot change who I am
for you or anyone else.
Nor can I change who I am.
Then we have nothing more
to say to one another.
So it would seem.
( door closes )
Sleeping alone?
I'm in no mood for
your foolishness, Q.
I knew there was something
different about you.
You seemed tense, preoccupied.
Somewhat... smaller.
At first, I thought it was
that horrible lecture of yours.
But I was mistaken.
Whatever game it is
you want to play,
it will have to
wait until tomorrow.
I had such high hopes
for you, Picard.
I thought you were
a bit more evolved
than the rest
of your species.
But now, I realize you're just
as weak as all the others.
Still, it pains me to see
the great Jean-Luc Picard
brought down by a woman.
What woman?
( chuckles )
Don't play coy
with me, Captain.
I witnessed your little
spat with Vash.
Nor will I soon forget
the look of anguish
on your face--
the pain, the misery.
If I didn't know better,
I would have thought
you were already married.
You must be very bored, Q.
Your imagination is
running away with you.
This human emotion--
love--
it's a dangerous
thing, Picard.
And obviously, you're
ill-equipped to handle it.
She's found a
vulnerability in you.
A vulnerability I've been
looking for for years.
If I had known sooner,
I would have appeared
as a female.
Mark my words, Picard.
This is your
Achilles' heel.
Believe what you wish.
Do you deny that you
care for this woman?
Believe me, I'd be
doing you a big favor
if I turned her into
a Klabnian eel.
Stay away from her, Q.
I was just trying to help.
My debt to you--
Is hereby nullified.
I don't want your help,
your advice, your favors,
or, for that matter, you.
Do you understand
once and for all?
You would have me
stand idly by
as she led you to
your destruction?
Yes!
As you wish.
( audience members
talking quietly )
Ladies and gentlemen,
members of the
Archeology Council, welcome.
Mystery.
It is the mystery
of Tagus Three
that brings us
here together today.
It is a mystery
that has invited
more argument, more deduction,
more speculation
than the best
works of fiction.
And if you will excuse
the conceit,
I want to tell you
about my detective story.
For several years now,
I have been trying
to unravel the secrets
of Tagus Three.
Needless to say,
I have not succeeded.
However, I have,
I believe,
turned up some
new information
that, if nothing else,
only raises a new set
of mysteries, and I hope
that we can discuss
them here together.
There have been 947 known
archeological excavations
conducted on the planet surface.
Of those, some 74
are generally believed
to have revealed
findings of
major importance.
The earliest were some
22,000 years ago...
( audience murmuring )
What the hell?
( sighs )
Q!
Is this Tagus Three?
I doubt there are many
oak trees on Tagus.
No, I think this is
supposed to be Earth,
somewhere around about
the 12th century.
And this is England-- or to be
more precise, Sherwood Forest.
At least Q's
re-creation of it.
That would explain
these costumes.
Quite right, Number One.
Or should I say,
John Little.
BEVERLY:
Well, if he's Little John,
that makes you--
PICARD: I know.
Robin Hood.
Sir, I protest.
I am not a merry man!
On the contrary,
Lieutenant Worf.
Your clothing
identifies you
with the character
of Will Scarlett.
Just as Geordi's mandolin
identifies him as Alan-a-Dale.
And you, Mr. Data,
bear a striking resemblance
to Friar Tuck.
I will not play the fool
for Q's amusement!
( hoofbeats,
horse whinnying )
I have you at last,
Robin Hood.
( Worf growling )
Quick, into the forest!
Mr. Worf!
That's an order!
SIR GUY:
Enough, you fools!
We'll never find them
in the greenwood.
( plucking mandolin )
TROI:
Like this?
DATA:
Yes. Now, string.
I've managed to stop
the bleeding.
( hoofbeats,
horse whinnying )
( horse whinnying )
Q.
It's about time you showed up.
I would prefer if you
addressed me as His Honor,
the High Sheriff
of Nottingham.
We will no longer share in this
pointless fantasy of yours.
Fine--
stay here and do nothing.
By mid-day tomorrow,
your crew will be
safely aboard their ship.
Of course, you will have to
accept the consequences
of your inaction.
Consequences?
What is the
one thing
that Robin Hood
is most famous for?
He robs from the rich
and gives to the poor.
Besides that.
Perhaps you are
referring to the rescue
of Maid Marion from
Nottingham Castle.
Q:
Yes, Data!
And it just so happens
that Sir Guy of Gisbourne
has decreed that Marion's head
shall come off tomorrow at noon.
Vash.
It's your choice,
Robin.
You can either take your ease
in this sylvan glade
or risk your life to save the
woman you care nothing about.
My feelings towards Vash
are irrelevant.
I would attempt to save any
innocent life, as you well know.
Yes, but what about
your merry men?
Are you willing to jeopardize
their lives as well?
Is Vash's life
worth more than
Data's or Troi's,
or Worf's?
You know, Worf, you'd make
a perfect throw rug
in Nottingham Castle.
( growls )
PICARD: Q, I ask you
to put an end to this
before someone gets hurt.
Oh, that's impossible.
You see, I've given this
fantasy, as you call it,
a life of its own.
I have no more idea
what's going to
happen than you do.
But of one thing,
I'm absolutely sure.
If you dare come to
Nottingham Castle,
blood will be spilled.
Oh, you'll wear yourself out
with all that pacing, m'lady.
I told you to stop
calling me that.
The name is Vash.
Oh.
My poor lamb.
You've got a brain
sickness, for sure.
Oh, can't I get you something
to ease your suffering?
I could use a drink.
Well, I wasn't thinking
of spirits, m'lady,
but I have some
nice fresh leeches...
to drain the fever.
Out!
Get out!
Oh, her mind's in an
awful turmoil, Sir Guy.
Who the hell are you?
( gasps )
M'lady!
Everyone in
Nottingham knows--
Sir Guy of Gisbourne.
Sir Guy of what?
Leave us.
Do not mock me,
Lady Marian.
I'm prepared to offer
you one last chance
to change your mind.
Will you marry me?
I see.
Then the execution will
proceed as scheduled.
What execution?
I warn you, Marian,
this pathetic attempt
at feigning madness
will not save your life.
You mean,
I'm the one being executed?
Sir Guy,
wait a minute.
Couldn't we talk this over?
I admit,
I haven't been myself lately.
Maybe we've both been
a bit hasty?
Please?
( playing badly )
Sorry.
( arrow landing )
TROI:
Data!
Are you all right?
The arrow impacted just above
my sixth intercostal support,
penetrating my secondary
subprocessor.
Fortunately, none of my
biofunctions seem affected.
Do not be concerned,
Counselor.
I believe your aim
is improving.
We've got to get out
of here, Captain.
Not we, Number One.
I want you and the others
to stay here until I return.
You're not going to try to
save her yourself, sir.
This is not a mission.
It's personal.
It's between Q and myself.
I don't want the rest
of you involved.
Captain!
You have your orders,
Commander!
And I expect you
to follow them.
A touch sharper, shall we?
Such benevolence,
Sir Guy.
Allowing the condemned prisoner
a breath of fresh air?
You're mistaken,
Sheriff.
Maid Marian has
promised to be my wife.
What?!
That's impossible.
VASH:
Not at all.
Though I admit a maiden
seldom has the opportunity
to win herself
such a noble husband.
Now, toast.
To the most beautiful
bride-to-be
in the whole of England.
Don't drink that!
It could be poisoned.
Have you taken leave
of your senses?
A foul scheme
of Robin Hood's.
She's in league with him,
I warrant.
Robin Hood?
Oh, Robin Hood!
Oh, well,
that was over long ago.
( scoffs )
All of Nottingham
knows you're still
in love with him.
VASH:
That's a lie!
He-- he bewitched me.
He put me under
some evil spell.
I suspected as much.
You can add sorcery
to the list
of charges
against that rogue.
Sir Guy, if anyone's been
bewitched here, it's you.
Silence!
Any more impudence,
and it'll be your head
on the block.
Guard.
Escort the Lady Marian
to her chamber.
But I'd much rather
stay here with you.
Of course you would,
my child,
but I have important
business to attend to.
Lovely creature.
Intriguing.
( chuckles )
( door opens and closes )
( noise outside )
One step closer, I'll scream.
( grunting )
Vash, damn it, it's me.
Jean-Luc!
Am I glad to see you--
you wouldn't believe
what I've been
going through!
One minute,
I'm on the Enterprise.
The next thing I know,
I'm here in Nottingham.
First, they're gonna
chop my head off.
Now, I'm supposed to
marry someone named Sir Guy,
and everyone insists
on calling me Marian.
Yes, I know.
You do?
But how?
You're Robin Hood.
My staff and I
were brought here
by an old adversary
of mine named Q.
But I'll tell you the rest
of that when we're safe.
Come on, we don't
have much time.
And the others
are outside?
They're waiting for us
back at Sherwood Forest.
You mean, you came
here alone?
That's right-- now, come on!
What kind of plan is that?
It's an excellent one--
if you'll just hurry up!
Do you realize our lives
are at stake here?
Only too well.
And this is the best strategy
you could come up with?
One man against
an entire castle?
You have a better one?
How about this?
You go, I'll stay here.
And do what?
Marry Sir Guy
if I have to.
Oh, that's brilliant.
If there's a way to escape,
I'll find it... eventually,
with my head still attached.
You really believe
I would leave you here?
I can take care
of myself.
You are the most stubborn
woman I ever knew.
Hey!
There'll be no escape for
you this time, Robin Hood.
You stay behind me.
You should have left
while you had the chance.
Well done, my dear.
Consider it my wedding gift
to you, darling.
Congratulations, Sir Guy.
I see you snared
the jackal.
It's Marian who
deserves the credit.
Took him with
his own sword.
You sent for me,
m'lady?
I want you to take this
letter to Robin's men.
You want me to go
to Sherwood Forest
at this time
of night?
You'll leave immediately.
But it's dark.
I'll get lost.
Besides, it's not safe,
what with all them
hedge robbers
and worse lurking about.
Please, this is urgent.
If you ask me, you'd be
better off with Sir Guy.
He's got a future.
Why, you'll be living in
London before you know it.
But you must go.
Otherwise, they'll kill him.
( snaps )
Out.
How dare you barge
in here like this?
I've come to apologize
for my harsh words.
I had no idea that
you were so ruthless.
That's most gracious of you.
I admit I was surprised,
but no more surprised
than Jean-Luc.
You're Q.
Yes, and you are a very
interesting woman.
What is this?
Give that to me.
A letter to Riker.
"Quick, come to
the castle.
Save the captain."
Why, this is wonderful!
What marvelous
duplicity.
You certainly fooled
Sir Guy, and me, as well.
I think you're worth
further study.
Am I?
Yes, but unfortunately,
we just don't have the time.
Guards!
Take this traitor away.
It appears there's going
to be a double execution.
VASH: This whole thing
is your fault.
PICARD:
My fault?
Yes, your fault.
If you hadn't
grabbed my sword,
we'd be back in
Sherwood by now.
I grabbed your sword
to prevent you
from being killed.
Oh, really?
Not as a wedding
present for Sir Guy?
You know I had no intention
of going through with that.
Do I?
You should never
have interfered.
You're the one
interfering.
I was just trying
to rescue you.
Well, next time,
don't bother.
Don't you worry, I won't.
Q: Don't the two of you
ever stop arguing?
Now tell me, Robin.
As you stand here
facing the termination
of your insect existence,
do you see what
brought you to this end?
Was she worth it?
Can we just get
this over with?
Are you implying
that I'm not worth it?
( scoffs )
Q, your game was
for my benefit.
She is innocent
in all of this.
Q: Ha! She is many things,
none of them innocent.
PICARD:
Let her go!
VASH:
Jean-Luc, you do care.
Q: A gallant gesture,
Robin, but a futile one.
Farewell. I hope the two
of you are happy together.
You have been
found guilty
of outlawry
and high treason.
Do you have anything to say
before sentence is carried out?
I...
Prepare them for the block.
( crowd chattering )
There are
too many of 'em.
Data, we need a
diversion, now.
Guards, take Marian
to the tower!
Come on.
I'll have you know,
I'm the greatest swordsman
in all of Nottingham.
( shouting )
Very impressive.
There's something
you should know.
And what would that be?
I'm not from Nottingham.
( approaching footsteps )
Jean-Luc.
Oh...
It's over, Q!
Get us out of here!
( sword hitting ground,
Q clapping )
My compliments, Picard.
I doubt Robin Hood himself
could have done much better.
If you have hurt
any of my people...
Q: Sadly enough,
they're all fine.
But my point is they
could have been killed,
and so might have you.
All for the love of a maid.
My debt to you,
Picard, is paid,
if you've learned how weak and
vulnerable you really are.
If you finally see how love has
brought out the worst in you.
Nonsense.
You're absolutely wrong.
It's brought out the
best in him--
his nobility, courage,
self-sacrifice...
tenderness.
Q:
Oh, you're good.
You're really good.
Enough of this.
Ah... indeed.
Is everyone here?
Where's Vash?
Computer,
locate Council Member Vash.
COMPUTER: Council member Vash
is not aboard the Enterprise.
Hello, Jean-Luc.
( sighs )
Well, this is a relief.
I thought that
perhaps Q had--
Well, he had some things
to discuss with me.
Indeed.
I'm surprised he's not busy
gloating over his victory.
He was right about
one thing, you know.
As ridiculous as it was,
his game did prove
that you still care.
I may not show my
feelings to my crew,
but I do have them.
I'm gonna miss you,
Jean-Luc.
So, where are you
off to now?
I haven't made up my mind.
After all, she has the entire
universe to choose from.
Meet my new partner.
Him?
Why not?
I'll tell you
why not.
Now, Jean-Luc,
let's not be unkind.
He's devious, and amoral,
and unreliable,
and irresponsible,
and...
and definitely
not to be trusted.
Remind you of someone you know?
As matter of fact, it does.
We're going to have fun.
I'm going to take her places
no human has ever seen.
Now, who can resist
an offer like that?
As payment in full
of your debt to me,
you will guarantee her safety.
She will not be
harmed, Jean-Luc.
I promise you that.
Well, are you going
to kiss her good-bye?
All right.
Well, aren't you?
Oh, I-- I'm sorry, I...
I forgot my hat.
Good-bye, Jean-Luc.