Captain's Log,
Stardate 44769.2.
For some weeks we have had
a Klingon exobiologist on board
as part of a scientific
exchange program.
Unfortunately, we suspect
that he was involved
in a security breach
and in the possible sabotage
of our warp drive.
What were you doing accessing
the propulsion system files
on Stardate 44758?
I didn't.
Yes, you did, from
computer 12B9, Deck 36.
The computer logged in
your identification
from your
communicator.
It must be a mistake.
J'ddan, we have
confirmed reports
that schematic drawings
of our dilithium chamber
fell into Romulan hands
one week later.
I know nothing about it.
I suppose you know nothing about
the explosion that disabled
the warp drive approximately
at the same time?
No, I was not involved.
You accuse me
because I am Klingon.
Our chief of security
is Klingon.
That has nothing
to do with it.
Send me home then,
if you are so distrusting.
We've already contacted
the Klingon High Council.
You'll be returned home as soon
as we finish our investigation.
I have
nothing more to say.
Very well.
Worf, accompany the lieutenant
to his quarters.
What do you think?
It's hard to tell.
He's very closed,
but he is hiding something.
On the Klingon home world,
your name is not mentioned.
It is as though
you never existed.
A terrible burden
for a warrior to bear--
to become nothing,
to be without honor,
without the chance
for glory.
I have friends--
powerful friends
on the home world.
I could talk to them.
They might help
to restore your name.
If you could just take me
to a shuttle craft.
It could be done
without anyone
knowing about it.
I don't know how
you transferred
secret information
to the Romulans,
but I will find out--
Pahtak!
And when we inform
the Klingon High Council,
they will put you
to a slow death.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
Retired Admiral
Norah Satie,
whose investigation exposed
the alien conspiracy
against Starfleet Command
three years ago
is arriving to assist
in our inquiry.
Captain Picard.
Admiral Satie,
welcome aboard
the Enterprise.
Delighted to be here.
I managed to acquire
my former staff.
My aide,
Sabin Genestra from Betazed,
and my assistant,
Nellen Tore
from Delb Two.
This is my first officer,
Commander William Riker.
May I show you
to your quarters?
Captain,
if Starfleet Command
was so concerned
with your report
they brought me
out of retirement,
I think I should get
right to work.
Very well.
Commander Riker, will you
see to the Admiral's staff?
First, I'd like to inspect
the damage to your engine room.
Admiral Satie,
this is Commander Data,
Commander La Forge.
Admiral.
We still can't get
in there, Captain.
The radiation levels
are dropping,
but they're still too high
to raise the isolation door.
How much longer
will it be?
At the rate
the levels are decreasing,
we will gain entry
in 49 hours, Captain.
Maybe the Admiral
would like to see
the visual log
of the explosion?
Yes.
This was logged
four days ago
at 0300 hours.
At that point, the emergency
confinement field was activated,
and the isolation
doors came down.
No one was killed,
but I have two people
in Sick Bay from
radiation burns.
Have you been able
to make any assessments?
DATA:
A slow-motion study
of the explosion
suggests that
the articulation
frame collapsed.
The schematics
that were stolen
from the Enterprise--
I believe some involved
the articulation frame
of the dilithium
chamber.
That's one reason we tend
to suspect sabotage.
Other evidence lends credence
to that theory, Captain.
A review of the sensor
logs indicates that
every system's reading was
well within normal parameters
until 52 milliseconds
before the explosion.
We haven't
found anything
that suggests
there was a malfunction
anywhere
along the line.
Captain,
I think I'm going
to need a full briefing
before we go
any further.
By all means,
Admiral.
SATIE:
Commander Data,
La Forge,
I don't envy you
your job.
Good luck.
There are very
disturbing overtones
in the idea of a Klingon
providing information
to the Romulans.
Are you aware of any other
Klingon-Romulan connection
that Starfleet might have
encountered recently?
I don't believe...
what Starfleet Command
knows or doesn't know
is for me to reveal.
This ship has
encountered...
several incidents
which might suggest
a potential alliance
between those
two powers.
We're well aware
of that, Captain.
What we must
concentrate on
is the business
at hand.
( chiming )
Come.
Excuse me, Captain,
I did not know...
Oh, please,
Mr. Worf, come in.
I particularly want
my guest to meet you.
Admiral Satie, this is
my head of security,
Lieutenant Worf.
Captain, I have
been pursuing
the investigation
of Lieutenant J'ddan.
I believe I know how
he transferred information
off the Enterprise.
Well done,
Lieutenant.
This is J'ddan's.
A hypo-syringe
he uses to treat
his Ba'ltmasor
syndrome.
But this has been fitted
with an optical reader
specially modified
to read data
from Starfleet
isolinear chips.
He can extract digital
information from a computer,
encode it in the form
of amino acid sequences,
and transfer those sequences
into a fluid in the syringe.
Then he injects
someone.
Perhaps even without
their knowledge.
Or perhaps
with their knowledge.
The information would be
carried in their bloodstream
in the form of
inert proteins.
The body itself
becomes a conveyor
of top secret files.
Lieutenant Worf,
when we confront J'ddan,
I want you to conduct
the interrogation.
I would be honored.
Captain. Admiral.
Captain,
I predict that officer
will be extremely valuable
in this investigation.
I have tracked
the movements
of every person who has
left the Enterprise
since you have been here.
I traced
one Tarkanian diplomat
as far as
the Cruces system
where he disappeared
and has not
been seen since.
That proves nothing.
A hypo-syringe...
was discovered
in your quarters.
I take injections.
Everyone knows that.
But your injections
do not include
an optical chip reader.
This device has
but one function--
To transform
computer information
into biological
sequences.
The blood
of all Klingons
has become water!
Since the Federation
Alliance,
we are turned into a nation
of mewling babies.
The Romulans are strong.
They are
worthy allies.
They do not turn Klingons
into weaklings, like you.
SATIE:
Lieutenant...
how did you damage
the dilithium chamber?
I had nothing to do
with that.
You mean it was
sheer coincidence
that it was sabotaged after you
gave the plans for the design
to the Romulans?
I do not know.
I had nothing to do with it.
You've admitted
your crime.
Why lie now?
I am not lying.
Mr. Worf, you may
have him confined.
Sabin?
I believe
he's telling the truth.
He admits stealing
the files,
but not sabotaging
the dilithium chamber.
I get no sense
that he's lying.
But if you're right,
someone else may be
involved.
I think, Captain,
you have a bigger
problem on your ship
than just one Klingon
exchange officer.
I've seen this before.
A specter of conspiracy
on a starship
is a frightening one.
I can scarcely
believe it myself.
But I am so grateful
for your presence, Admiral.
If anyone in Starfleet
can help us, it's you.
Captain...
I find myself changing
my mind about you.
In what way?
When Starfleet
ordered me here,
it was with
the expressed command
that we work together
on this problem as equals.
My father taught me
to avoid partnerships.
Most of them are
woefully lopsided.
That sounds like
Judge Aaron Satie.
You knew my father?
Only from
his writings.
His judgments were required
reading at the Academy.
He was
an extraordinary man.
Every night,
at the dinner table,
he would pose
a question for debate.
My big brothers and I
would wrangle it around
from one side
and the other.
Father would referee.
And he kept
a stopwatch on us
so we would have
to learn brevity,
But he wouldn't
let us leave
until he thought
we'd completely
explored the issue.
I'm willing to wager that
you trounced your brothers
during those debates.
More than once.
Father loved it when
I nailed one of them
with some subtle
point of logic.
All that I am,
I owe to him.
He was a giant.
You must miss him
very much.
Captain, I always
preferred working alone.
That way,
if something went wrong,
I didn't have to go
far for the cause.
I resented you
being assigned to me,
but I was wrong.
We're going to be
quite a team.
J'ddan did not make
friends easily.
There are not
many to question.
You've done a thorough job,
Lieutenant.
I am strongly motivated
in this matter.
Yes, I can see that.
I don't mind telling you,
I'm surprised.
Frankly, when I first
heard about your father...
My father?
Yes.
There are some who believe
he betrayed your people
to the Romulans.
What he did
or did not do
is no one's concern
but my own.
Of course.
I only meant,
before I saw you in action,
I naturally considered
you to be a possible
security risk.
But I want you to know
you have the Admiral's
and my complete confidence.
You have nothing
to prove to us.
If there is
a conspiracy on board,
I promise you,
I will find it.
Good.
You know the ship,
you know the personnel.
You know exactly what
we're up against.
We're counting
on you, Lieutenant.
I will arrange for
the interviews to begin.
And how often did
Lieutenant J'ddan
come in for
his injections?
About once a week.
Did you administer
them yourself?
No.
Well, who did?
I had one of
my assistants do that.
Did you ever hear him
say anything,
anything that may have
seemed innocent at the time
that might now shed some
light on this investigation?
No, nothing.
In fact, he rarely
spoke at all.
Thank you,
Dr. Crusher.
We appreciate your time,
you're excused.
Mr. Worf, will you
bring in the next person?
Please sit down,
Mr. Tarses.
For the record,
will you tell us
your name and position?
Simon Tarses,
Crewman First Class,
medical technician.
Now I assure you,
Mr. Tarses,
this is
an informal inquiry.
We are not accusing
you of anything.
However, if you
would like counsel,
it can be provided.
No, sir,
I have nothing to hide.
Tell me, how long have
you held your appointment
aboard this vessel?
Since Stardate 43587.
Mr. Tarses,
your records state
that you were born
on Mars Colony.
That's right.
Then you are human?
Largely.
My paternal grandfather
was Vulcan.
Yes, I see that.
Tell me, what is
your relationship
with the Klingon,
J'ddan?
Um, he...
I mean, there's no
relationship.
He just came in
for his injections.
Did you give him
those injections?
Sometimes.
There were several of us,
actually.
I-- I might have
done it twice.
Did he ever make
any comments that might
in retrospect
be suspicious?
Not really.
He hardly ever talked.
Did you ever see him
outside Sick Bay?
Once or twice
in Ten Forward,
with a group of people...
but I never had
a conversation with him.
Thank you, Mr. Tarses.
I don't think there's
need for more, Captain.
You're excused,
crewman.
Mr. Worf...
Wait.
He's lying.
He's desperately frightened.
He's covering something.
It's clear that
he's frightened.
But that's hardly
an indication...
It's more than that.
He wasn't truthful.
He's covering a lie.
One so big,
it's overwhelming him.
I think
we found the man.
Admiral.
I have to tell you,
you must not expect me
to permit any action
against Mr. Tarses
solely on the basis
of Betazoid intuition.
Sabin has
uncanny instincts.
I've learned
to trust them.
I'm not happy about
this use of a Betazoid.
But you have
a Betazoid counselor.
Surely you're aware
of the advantages.
There is a difference
between a counselor
and an investigator.
Are you saying you never
use your counselor
during interrogations?
Yes, I do...
but I would not act
solely on the basis
of her instinct.
Nor do I.
But you're asking...
you're asking me
to restrict
Mr. Tarses' movements
solely on the basis
of Sabin's feeling.
If Counselor Troi
suggested to you
that someone on the ship
were dangerous,
would you not
act on that?
Observe him,
curb his activity?
Yes, I admit
I probably would,
and perhaps I should
re-evaluate that behavior.
Oh, nonsense.
Let's keep
our priorities straight.
The important thing is
to uncover
the conspiracy on this ship
and to prevent
further damage.
Now, if Tarses is
a possible saboteur,
you cannot allow him access
to sensitive areas of this ship,
and I strongly suggest
continuous surveillance.
If we had
clear evidence...
We will have
clear evidence.
Sabin and Lieutenant Worf
are continuing to investigate.
But if we don't
act until then,
it may be too late.
No.
I won't treat a man
as a criminal
unless there is
cause to do so.
And while you're
being so generous,
you give a saboteur
a chance to strike again?
Last time, it was
just a hatch cover.
What if next time
it's more serious?
What if lives are lost?
Can you afford
not to act?
LA FORGE:
Engineering to Captain Picard.
Yes, Mr. La Forge?
Captain, could you come
to Engineering right away?
We've got something
interesting to show you.
We'll be right there.
Captain, we finally got
in here about six hours ago,
and we've been going over it
inch by inch ever since.
We've made micro-
tomographic analyses
of the dilithium chamber,
the hatch mounting,
the blast pattern
from the explosion.
We did mass spectrometer
readings of the residue
for chemical contents,
sifted through the debris
for bomb fragments.
What did you find?
This is the frame
for the hatch.
It ruptured
right along here.
And when we take
a reading of that spot...
See?
I'm afraid I'm out of
my element, Commander.
You'll have
to interpret for me.
There are sub-micron fractures
in the metal casing.
That's right. A breakdown of
the atomic cohesive structure.
Yes, and what caused them?
DATA:
Those fractures suggest
nothing more than
simple neutron fatigue.
I would speculate that,
when the engine was
last inspected
at McKinley Station,
the hatch casing was
replaced with one
which had
an undetectable defect.
I believe, sir,
that the conclusion
to our investigation
must be that the explosion
was not intentional.
That's the way
I see it.
This wasn't
sabotage at all.
It was nothing more
than... an accident.
An accident?
I find that hard
to believe.
If my crew say
there was no sabotage,
you can be sure
there was none.
Let us keep our perspective,
gentlemen.
Just because
there was no sabotage
doesn't mean there isn't
a conspiracy on this ship.
We do have
a confessed spy.
And he had
confederates.
Do we know that for sure?
Of course he did.
Do you think J'ddan
could have come on board
the flagship of the Federation
and accomplish what he did
without help from within?
I agree, it would be
difficult.
But not impossible.
We should continue
to investigate Tarses.
He was hiding something.
Captain Picard,
Lieutenant Worf and I
have been working
well together.
I suggest we continue,
if for no other purpose
than to determine
Tarses's innocence.
Now please,
let me remind you,
he is innocent until he is
proved guilty.
Of course he is.
What Sabin is saying is
that he and Lieutenant Worf
would like
to establish
his innocence
unequivocally,
for his own sake.
Very well.
But let us put this to rest
as quickly as possible.
You've opened the hearing
to spectators?
It isn't good to have
closed-door proceedings
for too long.
It invites rumor
and speculation.
Nevertheless, Admiral,
I think it would be wise--
Because spies
and saboteurs
don't like the bright lights
of an open inquiry.
They're like roaches,
scurrying for
the dark corner.
This hearing is convened
on Stardate 44780
as a continuing
inquiry into
the activities
of crewman Simon Tarses.
Mr. Tarses,
for your own protection,
I have assigned
a counsel to you
in the person
of Commander William Riker.
Thank you, sir,
but I don't need protection.
I have not done
anything wrong.
Dr. Crusher,
have you observed
crewman Tarses with J'ddan?
Well, yes, he gave him
his injection.
I meant
outside of Sick Bay.
I think so.
Perhaps in Ten Forward.
And whom else have you
observed at these occasions?
I don't understand
what relevance that has.
It was an innocent
social gathering.
If it was so innocent,
why do you hesitate
to give us the names?
Thank you, Doctor.
( whispers: ) Admiral,
if you have a case
to make against
Simon Tarses,
you had better make it.
Otherwise I'm stopping
this here and now.
Mr. Tarses,
isn't it true
that you have access
to the biological
supplies in Sick Bay?
It's part of my job, yes.
J'ddan used suspensions
of deoxyribose
to carry the encoded
files he stole.
Isn't it true
one of your duties
is to prepare these
suspensions?
Several technicians
share that job.
And isn't it true that
your security clearance
allow you access to all the
stores and files in Sick Bay?
Access which you can
exercise at any time?
Because I have access
does not mean I...
What would you say if
I told you there is evidence...
that the explosion
in the engine room
was caused by
a corrosive chemical--
one that is kept
stored in Sick Bay?
I had nothing to do
with that.
How can we believe you?
How can we believe
someone whom we know...
we know to be a liar?
I object,
there is no basis
for calling
crewman Tarses a liar.
Agreed. Mr. Sabin...
Captain, there is a basis
which will become clear
in a moment.
Mr. Tarses, didn't you
deliberately and premeditatively
lie when you filled out
your personnel application
and compounded that lie by
repeating it to this committee?
What?
Isn't it true
that the paternal grandfather
of whom you speak
was not a Vulcan
but was in fact a Romulan?
That it is
Romulan blood you carry
and a Romulan heritage
that you honor?
We're waiting,
Mr. Tarses.
On the advice
of my counsel...
I refuse to answer
that question in...
in that the answer
might...
might serve
to incriminate me.
You and crewman Marcus
will coordinate
to track Tarses's movements
over the last five years.
Ensign Kellogg, I want
a list of all relatives,
known associates,
and especially
old school friends.
And make
arrangements to do
an encephalographic
polygraph scan...
Mr. Worf.
Yes, Captain?
I need to speak
with you.
You are dismissed.
Please get your reports to me
as soon as possible.
Do you see what is
happening here, Mr. Worf?
Sir?
This is not unlike a...
a drumhead trial.
I do not understand.
500 years ago,
military officers
would upend a drum
on the battlefield.
They'd sit at it
and dispense summary justice.
Decisions were quick,
punishments severe,
appeals denied.
Those who came
to a drumhead were doomed.
But we know there is
a traitor here.
J'ddan has
admitted his guilt.
That's true, and he will
stand for his crime.
Tarses has all
but done the same.
How?
He refused to answer
the question
about his Romulan
grandfather.
That is not
a crime, Worf!
Nor can we infer his guilt
because he didn't respond.
Sir, if a man were not afraid
of the truth, he would answer.
Oh, no.
We cannot allow
ourselves to think that.
The seventh guarantee
is one of the most
important rights
granted by
the Federation.
We cannot take
a fundamental principle
of the constitution
and turn it against a citizen.
Sir, the Federation
does have enemies.
We must seek them out.
Oh, yes.
That's how it starts.
But the road from
legitimate suspicion
to rampant paranoia
is very much shorter
than we think.
Something is wrong
here, Mr. Worf.
I don't like
what we have become.
There you are,
Mr. Tarses.
Would you care
for some lemon?
No, thank you, sir,
this is fine.
Well, tell me a little
about yourself, crewman.
I know you were born
on Mars Colony.
Yes, sir.
All my life,
I wanted to be in Starfleet.
I went to the Academy's
training program
for enlisted personnel.
I took training as
a medical technician,
and I served
at several outposts.
The day that I was posted
to the Enterprise
was the happiest day
of my life.
Did you ever consider
applying to the Academy,
going the whole route?
Apply to become an officer?
My parents wanted me to,
and I thought about it.
I used to sit under
this big tree
near the parade grounds.
An elm tree with
a circular bench?
Yes, that's the one.
I spent many
an hour there.
It was my favorite
spot to study.
I used to sit
under that tree
and watch the drills.
Picture myself
an officer.
I know that it would have made
my mother very happy,
but I...
You didn't do it.
No.
I was 18 and eager.
The last thing I wanted
was to spend four years
sitting in classrooms.
I wanted to be
out there,
traveling the stars.
I didn't want to wait
for anything.
Now it's done,
isn't it?
My career in Starfleet
is finished.
Not if you aren't
guilty, Simon.
It doesn't matter.
I lied on
my application.
And that mistake will be with me
for the rest of my life.
Mr. Worf has
found a brother
who still lives
on Mars Colony.
Contact someone there
and have him interviewed.
Admiral Satie?
And start
a background checkup
into all his friends
at the Academy
training program.
Admiral Satie?
Yes, Captain?
I would like to have
a word with you.
Of course.
In private.
And off the record.
Of course.
After all, you are
my partner in this.
I cannot possibly
believe you mean this.
But I do.
This must stop.
It has gone too far.
You lied to him
about the engine room.
There were no volatile
chemicals found there.
It was a tactic-- a way
of applying pressure.
We're hounding
an innocent man.
And how, may I ask, have you
managed to determine that?
I've talked with him.
I see.
And he told you he was
a victim of circumstance.
Blameless and pure?
No, he admits
his mistake
in falsifying
his application,
but that does not
make him a traitor.
How can you be
so incredibly naive?
Captain...
may I tell you how I have
spent the last four years?
From planet to starbase
to planet.
I have no home.
I live on starships
and shuttlecraft.
I haven't seen
a family member in years.
I have no friends.
But I have a purpose.
My father taught me from
the time I was a little girl
still clutching a blanket
that the United
Federation of Planets
is the most remarkable
institution ever conceived,
and it is my cause
to make sure that
this extraordinary union
be preserved.
I cannot imagine
why you are trying
to block this
investigation.
There have been others
in the past who doubted me.
They came to regret it.
The hearings on
Simon Tarses will stop.
If necessary, I will go
to Starfleet Command.
I have news
for you, Captain.
I've been in constant contact
with Starfleet Command.
The hearings are
not going to stop.
They're going to be
expanded.
What are you saying?
I'm going to get
to the heart
of this conspiracy
if it means investigating
every last person
on this ship.
And every hearing
from now on...
will be held
in the presence
of Admiral Thomas Henry
of Starfleet security.
I've requested he be
brought here at once.
You never told me
about this.
I report to Starfleet
Command directly.
I do not need
your permission
or your approval
for my decisions.
Admiral.
What you're
doing here...
is unethical...
it's immoral.
I'll fight it.
Do what you must,
Captain.
And so will I.
Captain, warp engines
are back online.
We are ready to commence
restart sequences.
Sir?
Yes?
Yes, yes, of course,
proceed, Mr. Data.
You all right,
Captain?
Yes, of course, Number One,
just a little preoccupied.
Admiral Satie has
ordered you to report
to the interrogation room
at 0900 hours
tomorrow morning.
You are to be questioned
before the committee.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
Admiral Thomas Henry,
who has worked closely
with Norah Satie in the past,
has arrived to observe
the hearings.
Your full name?
Jean-Luc Picard.
Rank and position?
Captain, Federation
Starship Enterprise.
How long have you
held this post?
Over three years,
since Stardate 41124.
Very well.
Admiral.
If you don't mind, there is
something I would like to say.
If you have a statement,
you'll have an opportunity
to make it later.
I believe that
Chapter Four, Article 12
of the Uniform Code
of Justice
grants me the right
to make a statement
before questioning begins.
Very well.
I'm deeply concerned about
what is happening here.
It began when
we apprehended a spy.
A man who admitted
his guilt
and who will
answer for his crime.
But the hunt didn't
end there.
Another man...
Mr. Simon Tarses,
was brought to trial.
And it was a trial.
No matter what others
choose to call it.
A trial based
on insinuation...
and innuendo.
Nothing substantive offered
against Mr. Tarses,
much less proven.
Mr. Tarses'
grandfather...
is Romulan,
and for that reason,
his career now stands in ruins.
Have we become
so fearful--
have we become
so cowardly...
that we must
extinguish a man...
because he carries the blood
of a current enemy?
Admiral...
let us not condemn
Simon Tarses or anyone else
because of their
bloodlines
or investigate others
for their innocent
associations.
I implore you.
Do not continue
with this... proceeding.
End it now.
Captain, do you believe
in the Prime Directive?
Of course.
In fact,
it's Starfleet's
General Order Number 1,
is it not?
Your point, Admiral?
Would it surprise you
to learn that you have
violated
the Prime Directive
a total of nine times
since you took command
of the Enterprise?
I must say, Captain,
it surprised
the hell out of me.
My reports to Starfleet
will document
the circumstances
of those instances.
Yes, we're looking into
those reports, Captain.
Very closely
into those reports,
after which, I'm sure
we'll have more questions
for you about your
so-called commitment
to Starfleet
Prime Directive.
Captain,
could you tell us
just what happened
on Stardate 44390?
I beg your pardon?
Let me refresh
your memory.
You were transporting
a Vulcan ambassador, T'pel.
I was following orders
to take
this ambassador
to a location near
the Neutral Zone.
I don't think
we need the preamble.
In fact, she was not
a Vulcan at all, was she?
She was a Romulan spy.
That's correct.
A spy whom
you were delivering
back into the hands
of the enemy.
Tell me, Captain,
when the deception was revealed,
and she stood proudly
on the bridge
of a Romulan ship,
did you make any effort
to retrieve her?
PICARD:
No.
No? Even though
you knew
she carried
Federation secrets
that she had been
accumulating for years?
The Enterprise could have been
captured by the Romulans.
Captain Picard did
the only thing he could.
Really, Lieutenant.
And where were you
when this traitor
was on board
the Enterprise?
Where was
ship's security?
SABIN:
Don't you think it's
questionable judgment,
Captain, to have
a security officer
whose father was
a Romulan collaborator?
PICARD:
Lieutenant.
Tell me, Captain.
Have you completely
recovered
from your experience
with the Borg?
Yes, I have
completely recovered.
It must have been
awful for you.
Actually becoming
one of them.
Being forced to use
your vast knowledge
of Starfleet Operations
to aid the Borg.
Just how many
of our ships were lost?
39?
And a loss of life,
I believe,
measured at
nearly 11,000.
One wonders how you
can sleep at night,
having caused
so much destruction.
I question your actions,
Captain.
I question
your choices.
your loyalty.
You know, there are
some words I've known
since I was a schoolboy.
"With the first link,
the chain is forged.
"The first speech censured,
"the first thought
forbidden,
"the first
freedom denied,
chains us all irrevocably."
Those words were uttered
by Judge Aaron Satie
as wisdom and warning.
The first time
any man's freedom...
is trodden on,
we are all damaged.
I fear that today...
How dare you!
You who consort with
Romulans...
invoke my father's name
to support your
traitorous arguments?
It is an offense
to everything I hold dear,
and to hear those words
used to subvert
the United Federation
of Planets!
My father was
a great man.
His name stands for
integrity and principle.
You dirty his name
when you speak it.
He loved
the Federation,
but you, Captain,
corrupt it.
You undermine
our very way of life.
I will expose you
for what you are.
I've brought down
bigger men than you,
Picard.
I have nothing more
to say.
Perhaps we should call
a recess until tomorrow.
Am I bothering you,
Captain?
No, please,
Mr. Worf, come in.
It is over.
Admiral Henry
has called an end
to any more hearings
on this matter.
That's good.
Admiral Satie has
left the Enterprise.
We think we've
come so far.
Torture of heretics,
burning of witches is
all ancient history,
and then, before
you can blink an eye,
suddenly it threatens
to start all over again.
I believed her.
I... I helped her.
I did not see
what she was.
Mr. Worf, villains who
twirl their moustaches
are easy to spot.
Those who clothe
themselves in good deeds
are well-camouflaged.
I think,
after yesterday,
people will not be
so ready to trust her.
Maybe.
But she,
or someone like her,
will always be
with us.
Waiting for the right climate
in which to flourish.
Spreading fear
in the name of righteousness.
Vigilance, Mr. Worf.
That is the price we have
to continually pay.