Counselor Deanna Troi,
Personal Log, Stardate 44805.3.
My mother is on board.
Jean-Luc, you
delicious man!
You were just
thinking of me
weren't you?
As a matter of fact...
Well, think no
further, dear heart.
She's here.
Yes, indeed.
Oh, serious.
You're always so serious.
Lwaxana...
Hmm?
As a matter of fact,
I am rather busy at the moment.
And you're always busy
with something or other.
( chuckles ):
Never the right
thing, though.
My daughter tells me
that we're, um, picking up
someone interesting here.
Yes, the leading scientist
from Kaelon II, and...
Oh, Kaelon II!
I've never
heard of that.
Well, Lwaxana, it is something
of a rather delicate...
Oh...
...situation.
It's the first real contact
with a rather reclusive race
and... this is in the nature
of an official greeting, so...
Oh, diplomacy.
Oh, I adore diplomacy.
Everyone dresses so well.
Mr. O'Brien, energize.
Dr. Timicin,
I'm Jean-Luc Picard
Captain of the Enterprise.
This is Lieutenant Commander
La Forge.
I beg your pardon, Captain.
This is my first time aboard
a Federation starship.
Oh, yes, they told me.
The shaking of hands--
a form of greeting.
( clears throat )
I beg your pardon.
Dr. Timicin, allow me
to present
Lwaxana Troi of Betazed.
She is also
a guest on board...
And Daughter of the Fifth House
Holder of the Sacred Chalice
of Rixx
Heir to the Holy Rings
of Betazed
and what are you doing
for dinner?
Well, I don't know really.
Lwaxana, we have quite
a bit of work planned.
Well, the man's
never been
on board a starship
before, Jean-Luc.
Certainly somebody ought
to make him comfortable
before you get started.
Well, it seems
that Mrs. Troi
is our acting ambassador
of goodwill for today.
You just think of me
as your entertainment director.
( chuckles )
That man's in
a lot of trouble.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44805.7.
For generations,
the people of Kaelon II
have been working
to revitalize their dying sun.
The Federation has offered
to assist in testing
what may be a solution
to this problem.
Of course, the basic theories
of helium fusion enhancement
have been discussed
for over a century
but there's been no practical
method of application
until now.
DATA:
The modifications you have made
in the torpedoes guidance
systems are remarkable, Doctor.
Well, we'll see.
They still have to be proved.
But now at least it's possible.
I'd never dared to hope
for such a perfect match
with our own sun.
My only regret is that
it took us three years
to find a suitable sun
after you had
first contacted us.
We're not used to dealing
with other worlds.
We're not used to asking
for anything from others.
Your offer of help
has given us a possible
means of survival.
It has taken
40 years of my life
to develop the programming
that will control
your photon torpedoes.
It has been my life.
Thank you for this opportunity.
My only wish has been to find
a way to revive our sun...
before I die.
Mrs. Troi, I must protest
your unauthorized presence
on the Bridge.
What does that little
one do, Mr. Woof?
Please, madam!
That is a torpedo
launch initiator, and...
And it is "Worf,"
madam, not "woof."
Oh... ah!
There you are, my dear.
Where have you been?
I've been waiting
for you.
So nice to see you again
so soon.
Mrs. Troi.
Mother, what
did you want?
What?
You were waiting
for me.
Oh, yes, dear,
of course I was.
You really must let me
do something to relieve
the tedium
of all this work,
work, work.
I'm afraid I'm expected
in Engineering.
I'm really terribly sorry.
Oh.
Mrs. Troi
I have to ask you
to clear the Bridge, please.
I don't see why.
There are lots
of other people here.
Mother, please.
Well, don't you worry.
We'll just have our
little chat later.
I'd never have thought her
old enough to be your mother.
She is so...
vibrant.
If you look at the next
simulation, you'll see
that we need the temperature
to stabilize at 220 million.
Otherwise there's a secondary
then a tertiary
reaction to the...
Ah, ah, ah!
Enough is enough.
Rescue is at hand.
Ah, Dr. Timicin.
Oh, would you clear
all this mess
off the table,
please?
This mess, Mrs. Troi...
Now, now, now.
You boys have been
shut up in here
for hours.
Now, if you don't
eat something
you're going to get sick
and who's that
going to help?
I've made some
perfectly marvelous
Mantickian paté.
Mr. Homn
will lay it out
for us.
Oh, Mr. Homn is my valet.
He doesn't say much.
( sotto voce ):
How can he?
It is true that the
intellectual efficiency
of high-order beings does
diminish proportionately
with the deprivation
of nutritious fuel...
All right, all right.
Don't you start.
TIMICIN:
Mrs. Troi,
you're a wise woman.
I'm sure we could use a respite.
These two call me Mrs. Troi.
You call me Lwaxana.
Mr. Homn...
spread it.
So, knowing
my daughter's starship
would be passing fairly close
to Betazed again
I maneuvered a ride
and, um, here I am.
Deck eight.
I also have
a grown daughter.
She has a small son
of her own.
Oh. Then, you're married.
My wife died
quite some years ago.
You know, one thing
I don't understand.
If your people have
known for generations
that their sun is dying
why not simply
evacuate the planet?
It is our home.
It defines who we are
as a people.
If Kaelon II
ceases to exist
so do we.
Well, then you
definitely
should fix it.
With the Federation's help,
I... I hope we will.
And the Federation
will be pleased
to offer whatever
help it can.
Would you come in
for a nightcap?
Well, that's extremely
kind of you, but...
My valet sleeps elsewhere.
( both chuckling )
You're delightful.
You make me laugh.
( laughing )
I mean, I-I don't mean
that your invitation
makes me laugh.
I mean, I take that
quite seriously.
I-I mean...
Oh, but... Don't...
Just say yes.
I'll make you
laugh some more.
I wish I could...
but I must say no.
Good night, Lwaxana.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44807.5.
The Enterprise has arrived
at the Praxillus system
where we will conduct
Dr. Timicin's
helium ignition test.
Mother, how much...
Little One,
why do you
refuse to use telepathy
even when we're alone?
We're not
alone, mother.
Now, how much longer
is this going to take?
You've been selecting
for 20 minutes.
I am a woman
dressing for a man.
Something you might try
now and then, dear.
I wonder if Timicin
likes green.
That's not very
telepathic of you.
Oh, I tried telepathy on him.
He's the wrong species.
Right species
for everything else, though.
You might try that
once in a while, too.
You know,
you're not just incorrigible
you're insatiable.
( laughing )
I have completed
long-range scans.
There are no other life-forms
present in this system.
Spacecraft?
None within sensor range.
Picard to Engineering.
Mr. La Forge,
the system is clear.
Final pre-launch diagnostic,
level-5.
All systems verified.
We're ready here
when you are, Captain.
Very well.
Mr. Worf?
Photon torpedoes armed...
and targeted.
Fire in sequence.
First volley released.
Tracking torpedoes.
Entry program confirmed.
Second volley released.
Torpedoes now entering
the stellar core.
Their shields are holding.
Guidance systems normal.
Ignition sequence,
six seconds...
five seconds...
four...
three seconds...
now.
Shock wave patterns
within predicted range.
1700 percent rise
in gamma radiation levels.
Helium fusion rate...
increasing.
What about heat
and pressure levels?
Steady so far.
Density at 1100 grams
per cubic centimeter.
Temperature approaching
60 million degrees Kelvin.
We want it to stabilize
at 220 million.
Pressure wave
harmonics dispersing.
Temperature
in target zone increasing
to 81 million degrees, sir.
LA FORGE:
Still rising.
Temperature at
90 million degrees Kelvin.
And now 110 million.
Looking good.
One hundred
thirty-seven...
Radiation and pressure levels
still stable.
LA FORGE:
Temperature is
170 million degrees Kelvin.
One ninety...
and now, 200 million.
It's happening.
207... and rising.
Two nineteen...
and twenty.
Two twenty...
and holding.
Looks like
congratulations
may be in order.
Mr. Data?
Turbulence
patterns
are within predicted
parameters.
( console beeping )
Two twenty-two.
Temperature is rising
in the core again, Captain.
230 million
degrees Kelvin.
LA FORGE:
Still rising, Captain.
Two fifty-one.
Rate exceeding critical level.
Core density is becoming
unstable.
Let's get
the hell out of here.
Ensign, warp two, now!
I'm sorry.
Captain Picard?
Doctor.
Permit me to express
my appreciation
to you and your crew.
I am most grateful.
Most grateful.
Ensign, lay in a course
for Kaelon II.
Warp factor five.
Aye, sir.
( doors open, close )
I'm so sorry, Timicin.
I had one of those
named after me once.
Brilliant, young astronomer
from Rigel IV.
Of course, I, um, I sparkled
a bit myself in those days.
You see, that's called
fishing for a compliment.
You're supposed to tell me
I still sparkle.
I'm sorry.
I'm not helping, am I?
You're very kind.
I'm just not adequate
company right now.
Oh, that's all right.
I can make enough conversation
for both of us.
( chuckles )
I'll leave you alone.
No.
Please stay.
I wanted to tell you
how much I wish we
had met years ago.
What difference
do a few years make?
Unfortunately,
a great deal.
You see, Lwaxana,
I'm on my way home now...
to... die.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44812.6.
We have returned to Kaelon II
and established contact with
Science Minister B'tardat.
The experiment achieved
a stable core temperature
for a short time, Minister.
That's a significant
step forward.
We've been studying the sensor
logs and the torpedo telemetry
to determine if there was
any malfunction.
If there was and we are able
to isolate the problem
another test
might be successful.
And in the meantime,
all of our facilities
would be made available
to Dr. Timicin.
A most thoughtful
and generous offer
but Timicin has obligations
at home
and it would take us some time
to select a replacement.
We would be more
than willing
to extend our visit, sir.
That will not be necessary.
We'll contact you
as soon as we're ready.
We expect Timicin to return
home as soon as possible
and again, gentlemen,
many thanks.
( door chimes )
Come.
Are you aware these people
you are so graciously helping
are murderers?
I beg your pardon?
Well, the next thing to it.
When a person on this
benighted little planet
reaches the age of 60--
which Timicin is about to do--
they're expected
to simply kill themselves.
Did you know that?
Mr. Data?
The people of Kaelon II
are isolationists
almost to the point
of being xenophobes.
Regrettably, we know very little
about their customs.
Well, I know.
Timicin himself just told me.
He is supposed to go down there
to his loving friends
be wined, dined, honored
for his achievements
and then kill himself.
It's a barbaric ritual.
The, um... "The
Resolution," it's called.
Obviously, you can't
let him go, Jean-Luc.
I'm afraid I have no choice.
I don't think
you've been listening to me.
The man is supposed
to kill himself.
Now, you don't
just let that happen.
You don't just
turn your back.
What's the matter
with you?
Lwaxana, I'm sorry, but
whatever my personal feelings
I have no jurisdiction here.
I simply cannot interfere.
But you have to.
In a situation like this, you
absolutely have to interfere.
You've got to go
down there.
Talk to those
people, Jean-Luc.
Open their eyes-- educate them.
The Prime Directive
forbids us to interfere with
the social order of any planet.
Well, it's your Prime Directive,
not mine.
( door opens, closes )
Computer, locate
Counselor Troi.
What do you mean
I can't go down there?
Are you telling me that I'm
a prisoner on this ship?
Mother, what's going on?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry, Counselor.
I'm not sure
what to do here.
Well, I am sure.
I am a Betazoid ambassador.
I'm a Daughter
of the Fifth House
and those people are
going to answer to me.
So, y-you just energize
this damn thing
and get me down there!
He can't, Mother.
He has his orders.
His orders don't apply to me.
No, they apply to him.
And don't you try your
professional patronizing
on me, young lady.
They expect Timicin to die,
don't you realize that?
Just because he's 60.
What's 60?
It's nothing.
( sobbing )
I'll go check
the pattern buffers.
Come on, Mother,
let's sit down.
I-I'm sorry, Little One.
I-I don't know
what's wrong with me.
I'm... I'm sorry.
There's no need to be.
But I'm crying.
I don't cry.
You cried when father died.
You remember that?
Of course I remember.
We both cried.
But... but this
isn't the same.
Is it?
What do you think?
Oh... I-I don't know.
I... I just can't accept
that... that fate
would allow me to
meet him like this
and then take him away.
I mean, he's not ill.
He hasn't had
a tragic accident.
He's just going to die
and for no good reason.
Because his society
has decided that's he's too old
so they just dispose of him.
As... as though his life no
longer had any value or meaning.
You can't possibly
understand at your age,
but, well, at mine...
Well, sometimes you
feel tired and-and afraid.
You're feeling
very vulnerable.
Very mortal,
if I may say so.
But I know you, Mother,
and believe me
you will never be one of those
who dies before they die.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I've been studying
the preliminary reports
of the test.
I-I don't understand
where it went wrong.
I thought I had taken into
account all of the variables--
deep convection patterns,
proton reactions
neutrino count.
( sighs )
Oh.
I will say it again--
you are a kind woman.
No, no,
I'm a hateful woman.
I hate what
you're going to do
and I hate you for doing it.
It is the way of my world.
I wish you
could accept that.
I never will.
Never.
How long have you
been sitting there?
Oh, I don't know--
a minute, an hour.
Lwaxana...
Do you want anything?
Some tea?
I want to explain.
I want... very much
for you to understand.
15 to 20 centuries ago,
we had no Resolution.
We had no such concern
for our elders.
As people aged, they...
Their health failed.
They became invalids
and those whose families
could no longer care for them
were put away
into deathwatch facilities
where they waited in loneliness
for the end to come
sometimes... for years.
They had meant something
and they were forced
to live beyond that
into a time of meaning nothing--
of knowing that they
could now only be
the beneficiaries
of younger people's patience.
We are no longer
that cruel, Lwaxana.
No, no, you're not cruel
to them, you just kill them.
The Resolution
is a celebration of life.
It allows us to end our lives
with dignity.
"Celebration of life."
Sounds very noble, very caring.
What you're really saying is
you got rid of the problem
by getting rid of the people.
It may sound that way
but it is a time
of transition--
one generation passing on
the responsibilities of life
to the next.
What about the
responsibility
of caring for
the elderly?
That would place a dreadful
burden on the children.
We raise them, we care for them,
we suffer for them
we keep them from harm
their whole lives.
Now, eventually, it's their turn
to take care of us.
No parent should expect
to be paid back
for the love
they've given their children.
Well, why the hell not?
Oskoids.
What's that?
Oskoids-- a Betazed delicacy.
Looks very interesting.
You should have tried it
while you were still alive.
No reason to bother now.
Why 60?
Why not 62? 58?
A reasonable age
had to be set.
But it's not reasonable,
certainly not in your case.
You're as vital and healthy
a man as I've ever known.
That is why I wish
to say good-bye
to my family and colleagues
while I am this way--
in full command
of my faculties
knowing that they will
always remember me
as a strong and
vigorous man.
But it makes no sense.
Some of your people could still
be active at 70 or 80
and others might
be seriously ill at 50.
How cruel of you
to make them
wait so long
to commit suicide.
Setting a standard age
for the Resolution
makes it uniform
for everybody.
To ask individual families
to decide when their
elders are to die--
that would be heartless.
I agree.
Why not let everybody die
when they die?
Lwaxana...
You have a grandson,
you said.
Yes, almost seven.
Well, wouldn't it be better
for him to know his grandfather?
I mean, not some vague memory
of someone who once loved him
but a real, living person
who does love him.
Don't you really think
that would be better?
I attended the Resolution
of my parents
when it was their time.
It was beautiful.
Lwaxana, this is
a custom that
I have known
and accepted all my life.
The women of Betazed
used to wear these enormous wigs
with large holes in the center
for tiny,
caged creatures.
Yes?
First, it was a fashion
then it went on long enough
to become a custom--
a tradition--
but it was uncomfortable
for the woman
and cruel to the animal.
So then one day,
one very formidable woman
finally said so--
refused to ever wear
another of those wigs.
Fairly soon, the custom stopped.
She had the courage to stand up
and fight for change.
She must have been
a lot like you.
Timicin, there is
no one more qualified
more experienced,
or more likely to save
their planet than you
and they would have
you kill yourself.
Younger scientists
will take my place.
My work...
the work will continue.
Your planet has what,
30, 40 years left?
What if your scientists can't
find the answer without you?
What then?
What chance do you
think your grandson has
of reaching the age of 60?
Enough, please!
It is my time, Lwaxana
and that is the way it is.
( sighs )
Well, if that's
the way it is,
I don't know why
anyone's bothering
to try to save
your planet at all.
If it's time has come,
let it die.
Where is the difference,
Timicin?
Where?
Convection boundary uncoupling.
The reaction... caused
gas turbulence of a totally
unexpected magnitude.
Why?
There was evidence
of a delayed surface shock.
No, I'd anticipated that.
I thought I'd anticipated
all possible variables
but stars, you know, they're
like living entities in a way--
quite unpredictable.
You know...
I wouldn't be
at all surprised if this
were a result of...
Look here.
42 seconds into the test,
there is a sudden rise
in the level
of hydrogen-alpha emissions.
And here is another.
I'm right, aren't I?
There had
to be neutron migration
within the star's inner core
as the reaction grew.
Perhaps, Doctor, but there
is no known method
for controlling
a neutron migration.
Yes, yes, but theoretically,
it is possible.
Using these test results,
we could construct
a new computer model
of the energy dynamic of a star
that can test
a new detonation program.
I'm certain it can be
accomplished, certain.
It's just a matter of time.
A matter of time.
( door chimes )
Come.
Timicin.
Time for you
to leave us then.
Captain...
I have come
to officially request...
asylum aboard the Enterprise.
Timicin, I cannot believe this.
Why asylum?
Asylum from what?
I turn 60 in four days,
Minister.
Yes, and your family
and colleagues
are already gathering
for your Resolution.
I believe that it is time for us
to reexamine
as a people,
the wisdom of the Resolution.
Are they forcing you into this?
Are you being coerced?
Influenced, perhaps.
Coerced? No.
Our only influence, Minister,
is by example.
Timicin's decision is his
own free will, I assure you.
I cannot believe that a man
of Timicin's stature
would freely choose
to reject his own culture.
No one on Kaelon II understands
this project as I do.
There are new theories
that would take others
a decade to test and confirm.
With my guidance, it could be
done in half that time.
I must finish my work.
Others started your work,
others will finish it.
It has always been this way.
It always will.
RIKER:
Captain, scanners indicate
two Kaelon warships
rising on an intercept course.
Acknowledged, Commander.
Minister, we are here
in friendship
hoping to be of assistance.
You have helped
quite enough, Captain.
I suggest you return Timicin
and depart.
If you attempt to leave orbit
with Timicin on board
our ships have
been ordered to open fire.
B'tardat, there's
no purpose at all
in letting this become...
( sighs )
It shouldn't have happened.
I've handled this poorly.
You acted in good
conscience, Doctor.
I don't see what else
you could have done.
I could have let
well enough alone.
I could have returned home.
What do you think, Captain?
Have I done... the right thing?
I'm afraid you're the only one
who can answer that.
Lwaxana would...
Would have me lead a revolt.
I'm only a scientist.
I wish I had her strength.
She is a woman of extraordinary
conviction, isn't she?
Isn't she.
Any communications, Number One?
No, sir.
We have an open channel.
WORF:
The warships are taking
a standard attack posture.
Staggered approach vectors,
within weapons range.
Shields up.
Red Alert.
Captain...
Doctor, I suggest that you
return to your quarters.
I don't want there
to be any bloodshed
because of my decision.
They will do everything
they can to avoid it.
I think we should get
out of their way now.
Yes, yes, of course.
I understand.
Mr. Worf, ascertain
their offensive potential.
Aye, sir.
We must transmit
the new analysis
of neutron migration,
immediately.
If I can make them see the
direction that I've taken...
LA FORGE:
We've already tried.
They refuse to accept
further reports
from you, Doctor.
They have to accept it.
If I can reestablish
a computer interface
with the Science Ministry...
They've disengaged
the linkup, Doctor.
Why don't they answer?!
Even if I find the solution,
you will not accept it?!
Because I do not
terminate my life
they terminate my work.
Alive, I am a greater threat
to my world than a dying sun.
But Jean-Luc will find
a way to settle this.
No.
He always does.
No, my decision
will only lead
to more distrust
of other worlds.
Nothing will change.
Now, don't be foolish.
I am not being foolish!
Lwaxana, I want to live
because I see in you
how much I have
to live for.
You make me realize
that my life
still has value.
I can be an example
to my people.
I can finish my work.
But discovering
these new desires
and not being able to do
anything about them--
not being able
to finish my work
not even being able
to reach my people...
You are making a statement
about the sanctity of life
and it will be
heard, Timicin.
Who will hear it
from light years away?
Where will I
go now, Lwaxana?
I'm a man without a world.
I can't go home.
Oh, Timicin...
RIKER:
Bridge to Dr. Timicin.
You have a visitor
coming aboard.
B'tardat?
No, sir,
it's your daughter.
Dara.
Father.
This is Lwaxana Troi.
She has been host
and friend.
I've been
looking forward
to meeting
you, Dara.
Whatever you have to say to me
can be said
in front of her.
I see.
Father, come home.
This is wrong.
Dara, if I could show you
the work I have begun.
There's still so much
for me to do.
There is nothing for me
to look at.
It is irrelevant.
Your father's
work
may save your world, my dear.
I would hardly consider that
irrelevant.
All I'm concerned with now
is you, not your work.
Your work is over.
It is your
time to rest.
LWAXANA:
Perhaps you will
feel differently
as you get
a little older--
say, approaching 60.
My father taught me
to cherish the Resolution.
I don't know
how you have poisoned him
to reject it.
It's an obscene ritual.
How dare you?
How dare you criticize
my way of life
and my beliefs?
Please, please.
Dara.
Please.
Where will you go?
Hmm.
I don't know.
And where will you die?
I cannot bear
the thought
of you being laid to rest
on some other world.
That you will not lie
beside my mother.
That I will not be able
to lie beside you
when my Resolution comes.
I'm sorry.
I don't know how you can
go on with your life
knowing that each day
is an insult
to everything we believe in.
( sighs )
Father, I love you...
but I am ashamed.
( sobbing )
I would like
to be alone now, please.
( sighs )
Well, I'm suddenly
not sure of myself.
It's a feeling
I-I'm not at all used to.
I... I don't think I like
it very much, Little One.
Not sure
of yourself?
My life has been full.
Oh... now and then, perhaps
it's overflowed a little, but...
but I-I enjoy living.
And now I'm asking myself
is it possible I was wrong
to encourage Timicin
to choose life?
You were honest
with him, Mother.
You had to be.
Maybe I want him to live
just to keep me company.
Of course, you do
but you didn't do
this for yourself.
You did it for him.
Did I?
Then look what I've
done to him.
He's like a...
He's like a man
who has lost his faith.
I never considered
how deeply ingrained
this Resolution liturgy is.
Ritual provides
structure in society--
good rituals and
bad rituals alike.
Well, this is a bad one.
Your point of view.
Well, it should be
the point of view
of any reasonably intelligent,
middle-aged person.
( sighs )
Unfortunately, it is not.
( door chimes )
I'll, uh... see
you later, Mother.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
You're going back.
Do you believe that I love you?
I do, you know.
But, finally,
if that is my only reason
to stay alive...
It's not enough.
Almost.
Almost, but not quite.
I can't be that
selfish, Lwaxana.
I am not the person
to lead the revolt.
I do apologize
for all the turmoil
that I've created.
Doctor, I would deeply regret it
if you were returning
only to ease
diplomatic tensions.
It is more... much more.
Then I wish you
and your people well.
When it is time
for another test
I will encourage
my people
to seek your
assistance again.
If for any reason
you would like
to wait for
a few minutes...
No, we have already
said our good-byes.
Lwaxana.
It is the custom
for your loved ones
to join you at this Resolution,
is it not?
You do not have to do this.
Yes, I do.
Permission to
disembark, Captain?
I promise I won't cause
any problems down there.
Permission granted.
We are ready,
Mr. O'Brien.