Doctor Beverly Crusher,
Personal Log, Stardate 44821.3:
Began an analysis today
of the respiratory problems
being experienced on
the Beta Moon of Peliar Zel.
Finally got an actual letter
from Wesley.
Topped the class
in Exobiology,
but he's still struggling
in Ancient Philosophies.
And... there's someone new
in my life.
Ambassador Odan, Dr. Crusher.
I was just on my way
to speak to you.
Hello, Data.
I've completed my study
on the atmospheric variations
which have occurred
on the moons since the new
technology was implemented.
Oh, thank you, Commander,
that will be most helpful
in my efforts to mediate
the quarrel.
I could go over it
with you now.
It would not require
more than two hours.
Oh, we-we do
appreciate that, Data,
but the Ambassador and I
have set aside this time
to analyze the incidence
of the lung disease
on the moons' inhabitants.
Then it is perfect timing,
Doctor.
What better occasion
to integrate my results
into your study?
Now that I think about it,
you're absolutely right,
Commander.
Unfortunately,
I'm not feeling very well.
Perhaps Dr. Crusher
could get you started
inputting your information.
I, myself, must return
to my quarters.
Ambassador, are you still
having those awful headaches?
I'd better bring you
a hypospray to take care of it.
I would be most grateful.
Okay.
Put a cold cloth on
your forehead, Ambassador.
I'll do my best to
be with you shortly.
I'll set you up with
the medical monitor, Data.
It'll take you a while to
input the figures, won't it?
At least an hour.
But I do not believe
much time can be saved
by exhibiting such
haste now, Doctor.
Data, there are times when
every second does count.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( chuckling )
Somehow, I had
an unnatural fear
that Data was going to barge in
and ask to discuss
the peripheral effects
of magnetospheric energy taps.
Well, if I don't get back
soon and take a look at
his projections,
he just might come
looking for me.
Do you know
when I first met
the formidable
Doctor Beverly--
what, uh, 10 days ago?
I thought to myself,
"This woman is ice...
through to her bones."
Who would have ever guessed
that instead of ice
there is fire?
Odan...
Stay here.
Don't go.
Odan, are we...
Is this interfering
with your work on
the Peliar Zel problems?
Well, fortunately,
I've done about as much
as I can until we get there,
because I just can't seem
to keep my mind
on my work right now.
Odan...
Mm-hmm.
I have to go.
No!
Promise me we'll be
together tonight.
I promise.
Then you may go,
Doctor Beverly.
It's just Beverly.
Not just Beverly.
It's Beverly's smile,
it's her kindness,
her beauty,
within and without.
So much more
than just Beverly.
PICARD:
Picard to Ambassador Odan.
ODAN:
Yes, Captain, this is Odan.
The Federation representative
from Peliar Zel has come on
board.
Would you care to meet us
in the observation lounge?
I'll be right there,
Captain.
If the news were encouraging,
I assume you would not be here.
I am afraid you are
correct, Captain.
The situation is growing
progressively worse.
( whispering )
Where have you been?
Uh, with a patient.
Minor emergency.
PICARD:
Ambassador Odan.
This is Governor Leka Trion
of Peliar Zel.
Ambassador,
thank you for coming.
I knew your father.
His efforts helped keep
our people at peace
for several generations.
I would hope to serve you
as well as he.
Governor,
Ambassador.
I hope Doctor Crusher was able
to help you with your headache.
Thank you.
Actually, she was.
Governor Leka has intercepted us
before we reach her planet
in order to update us
on the situation.
The people on our moons
have been in discord
ever since they migrated
from our planet
five centuries ago.
To us on the planet, they're
like two squabbling children.
We try to help them settle their
arguments by not taking sides,
but this time,
we are at a loss.
Well, I've been studying
the information you sent.
If I understand correctly,
the people of Alpha Moon
have found a way to tap
directly into the magnetic field
of your planet and now rely
exclusively on that
energy source.
Yes, but the Beta Moon
is now suffering
some environmental damage
as a result.
My design model suggests
that Beta will
eventually experience
rising temperatures,
erratic tide surges
and, in general,
the beginning of global warming.
The impact on the health
of the Betan people is clear.
There will be profound medical
repercussions.
Alpha is unwilling to give up
its newfound energy source.
Beta accuses them of
intentionally courting genocide.
Our efforts to reach
a compromise have failed.
And now we have
received intelligence
that both sides
are arming for war.
If that happens,
the people on my planet
will begin to take sides and the
outcome can only be disastrous.
We'll be in orbit around
Peliar Zel within six hours.
If you could arrange
for the representatives
of Alpha and Beta to be there,
then Ambassador Odan
could beam directly down
to the planet's surface.
Excuse me, Captain.
I prefer to shuttle
to the surface.
I would not recommend it.
There are many radical factions
involved in this dispute.
It would be difficult
to guarantee your safety.
Well, I'm sure I'm not the first
who has expressed discomfort
at the idea
of molecular transport.
Thank you, but I prefer
to remain intact.
I'll shuttle down.
As you wish.
Counselor, what is it?
It's Ambassador Odan.
I continually feel...
fluctuations of
emotion from him.
Perhaps it's perfectly
normal among the Trill.
It could be.
We know so very little
about them.
Yes... quite.
WOMAN: Hi, Deanna.
Hi.
Is that the colgonite
astringent
you have on your eyes?
Yes. I guess so.
I've never tried it.
Someone...
just put it on... me.
I didn't know
you even came in here.
I don't.
At least, um...
at least not very often.
But it feels good
to indulge yourself sometimes.
I guess so.
Especially when you haven't
done so in a while.
Wha-What is that
supposed to mean?
Beverly...
you're in love.
( sighs )
Sometimes I wish
you weren't so empathic.
( whispering )
I don't think it's
really a secret.
It isn't?
You've been glowing.
Oh.
Must be the astringent.
What?
Nothing.
Oh, yes, there is.
What is it?
( sighs )
It's just something
I sense in Odan.
What?
What do you sense?
It's just...
How well do you
really know him?
I feel I know him better
than I've known anyone
in my life.
Am I being foolish?
I don't think so.
And yet, I've only known him
for a couple of weeks.
Of course,
that could be infatuation.
But I am a grownup
and I know the difference
between love and infatuation.
Oh, all I know is...
I haven't felt this way
for a long time.
And you like it.
I like it.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to see me,
Captain?
Yes, Ambassador.
Please sit down.
We have entered orbit.
We shall be transporting
you to the planet
in a few minutes.
Oh, I am ready, Captain.
How will you proceed
when you're there?
Oh, I cannot answer that.
I... I never know until
I'm into the situation--
meet the people involved.
I work very much by instinct
and not by prearranged plan.
Well, it seems to
work well for you.
Well, I do like to go
into a situation
as well-informed
as possible.
And I must say that your staff
has been quite helpful
in briefing me
on the problems down there--
particularly Doctor Crusher.
My staff is quite capable.
I'm glad they've been useful.
Your Doctor Beverly is...
an extraordinary person,
both as a scientist and...
and as a woman.
Yes, I'm sure that's true.
Well, shall we make our way
to the Shuttle Bay?
Captain, you know
her better than I.
Do you have any idea
how committed she is to
remaining with Starfleet?
I wouldn't presume
to speak for her.
Oh, no, of course not.
I just thought...
Well, you've known her
so much longer than I.
TAGGERT: Ensign Taggert
to Captain Picard.
Yes, Ensign?
TAGGERT: The shuttle is ready
to transport the Ambassador.
Very well.
I'll find
my own way, Captain.
I hope to return
with good news.
Commander Riker has asked to
pilot you himself, Ambassador.
I am honored.
I don't know
when I'll be back.
I know.
Have a safe trip.
Oh, I will stay safe,
Doctor Beverly.
I have good
reason to return.
I've researched
Earth customs.
This flower is given
to express love.
Yes, it is.
Initiate shuttle
preflight sequence.
RIKER: Preflight underway,
counting to clearance.
Shuttle has cleared
the bay door.
Commander Riker, you will be out
of shield range in five seconds.
Acknowledged, Lieutenant.
We'll be entering the upper
ionosphere in 2:20 seconds.
Sir, an unidentified ship
is emerging from the limb
of the moon.
Hail the vessel.
RIKER: I have visual contact.
I don't recognize it.
It claims to be an escort vessel
from the Beta Moon.
There was no mention
of an escort.
Request a security
clearance code.
They do not answer, sir.
Commander Riker, prepare to
return to the Shuttle Bay.
RIKER:
Acknowledged.
Captain, they are loading
their phaser banks.
Increasing power
to the shields.
Coming about.
Engage tractor beam.
Report, Number One.
We've lost port thrusters
and both backup stabilizers.
I'm losing control.
PICARD:
We're bringing you in.
Captain, the shuttle hull
has been weakened.
We're breaking up.
You can't tow us.
You better beam us
directly on board.
No. Don't do it.
I can't stabilize the shuttle.
If you transport me,
it will kill me. Please...
PICARD: Number One,
we're ready to beam you aboard.
Belay that order, Captain.
I'll bring her in manually.
Advise Doctor Crusher
we have a medical emergency.
CRUSHER: He's in shock,
He's lost a lot of blood,
but that still doesn't
explain these readings.
Eosinophilia in the
cerebrospinal fluid at 46%.
Sedimentation rate is 29,
but his lymphocytes
are still intact.
It's as though there's
a parasite at work.
Odan?
Odan...
I need to do
exploratory surgery.
You may have
a parasitic infection.
You must not.
You won't survive.
What is that?
Beverly...
that is me.
What?
This body is just a host.
I am that parasite.
That is what
must survive.
It has always been
this way.
The Trill
are a joined species...
a host and a symbiont...
and in this fashion,
we have survived for millennia.
You're dying.
What can I do?
The host body is dying.
You must contact
the Trill quickly.
Tell them I need another host.
They will send
a replacement.
I know this is
difficult to accept...
but I beg you,
Doctor Beverly...
help me.
This mission
must be completed.
Odan's host body
died of the injuries
just over an hour ago,
but the symbiont being,
Odan, is still alive.
Odan is the one who
negotiated the last treaty.
But the man everyone
thought was his father
was just another
host body.
And the reason Odan
refused the transporter?
It would have damaged
the symbiont.
We've contacted
the Trill.
Another host will be here
in 40 hours.
I've placed
Odan in stasis.
He can survive another
hour, maybe two,
but not beyond that.
Would it be possible for me
to serve as a temporary carrier?
No, Data.
The relationship requires
a biological being.
We're at a desperate impasse
in the Peliar system.
The attack on the shuttlecraft
has inflamed the dispute.
Who was responsible?
No one will
admit anything.
Each side accuses the other
and the threats are mounting.
We need Odan.
Doctor, could
a human host carry him?
I believe so.
From Odan's description
of the process,
it should be possible,
but I don't have...
Then I volunteer.
There's been no precedent
for a human host.
I couldn't guarantee
what might happen.
The risk is too great,
Commander.
Weigh it against
the prospect of war.
It's your choice, Will.
Let's get to it.
I've given you
a local anesthetic.
You must be conscious
during the implantation.
Drugs might damage
the symbiont.
I understand.
Laser scalpel.
( sighs )
( scalpel humming )
How do you feel?
Is there any pain?
No, just some
strange sensations.
Vital signs?
Heart rate 110.
Blood pressure 90 over 40.
I can't close yet.
The assimilation's not complete.
OGAWA: Pulse 130 and climbing.
EEG is erratic.
He's going to start
fibrillating.
200 milligrams
of metrazene.
WOMAN:
Yes, Doctor.
Hang on, Will.
We've got
incorporation, Doctor.
I'm closing.
OGAWA:
Brain waves are
still irregular.
The metrazene should
have stabilized him.
I'll give it ten more seconds
before I go in again.
Here we go.
EEG approaching regular.
Blood pressure leveling off.
That's better.
Signs are returning to normal.
Will...
it's Beverly.
Can you hear me?
Hello.
You're going to be all right.
How do you feel?
I'm fine.
You look a little tired,
Doctor Beverly.
I know this must be
disturbing, Governor,
but you must convince
the inhabitants of the moons
that I am Odan.
I have his skills,
his thoughts, his memories.
They will perceive you
as a Starfleet officer--
perhaps with
your own agenda.
The man they knew
as my father...
the man who stands
before them...
both are merely hosts.
It is your task to
help them understand.
I will try.
I cannot promise
they will listen.
They are more factionalized
than ever.
Listening is a skill
which seems to have evaporated
with the heat of argument.
Speak softly, Governor.
Those who cannot
hear an angry shout
may strain
to hear a whisper.
I will do what I can.
Well done.
Mr. Worf, will you escort
the Ambassador to his quarters?
I'm just
a little dizzy.
I'll be fine.
I just need to lie down.
Picard to Doctor Crusher.
CRUSHER: Yes, Captain?
Doctor,
the Ambassador is not well.
Will you please attend to him
in his quarters?
Right away, sir.
White cell count
is elevated.
Six-tenths of
a degree temperature.
But no sign of rejection.
That's good.
You look awfully pale.
Just a little weak
and lightheaded.
Cerebral blood flow
looks normal.
I'll leave
a metabolic booster.
Use it if the symptoms
get worse.
Beverly...
Beyond that,
I don't know what to do.
This is all new to me.
It is new to me,
as well.
Please don't go.
We've got to talk
about this.
I don't know what to say.
Nor do I.
But I know that
the silence would injure us.
Well, maybe you should have
thought about that sooner.
Maybe you should have
told me what you were.
It didn't seem to bother you
to remain silent yesterday.
It never occurred to me.
This is what I am.
Did you ever tell me that
you were only a single being?
Of course not.
It was normal to you.
I don't know who you are!
You must understand.
Whoever I... whoever I seem to
be, I am Odan,
who loved you.
That has not changed.
I still love you.
I can't help that!
If this causes you pain,
I will suppress it.
I will keep
my distance.
Doctor Beverly...
I would never hurt you.
( conversation and laughter )
May I join you?
You know, Deanna,
the first man
I ever loved unconditionally
was named Stefan.
He was a soccer player,
and I would watch him
as he would race
down the field.
And I thought my heart
would stop
because he was
so beautiful.
We married
and had three children--
twin boys,
Andrew and Alexander,
and then later,
a little girl, Jennifer.
Stefan became an artist...
very famous.
He created huge,
breathtaking
metal sculptures.
He came to adore me
as much as I worshipped him--
in my daydreams at least.
Stefan was 11
and I was eight.
He never even
knew I existed.
Oh, Deanna...
I loved Odan.
I'm sure of it.
I had no doubts, no fears.
But what was it I loved?
His eyes?
His hands?
His mouth?
They're gone.
If that was all it was,
I should mourn him
and go on.
But it was more than that.
I felt...
completely free with him...
unguarded...
at ease with myself.
There were so many things
that made him special to me.
And where are they?
Are they still here,
alive in Will Riker?
I look at Will,
and I see...
someone I've known
for years...
a kind of brother.
But inside...
is he really Odan?
Oh... help me.
Please.
What do your
feelings tell you?
I feel his pull.
It's very powerful.
I wish he'd never
come on this ship.
Don't wish that,
Beverly.
You can't be open to love
if you don't risk pain.
I don't care.
I'd give anything not to feel
the way I do now.
( door opens )
He's here, isn't he?
Look at him.
I don't want to look at him.
Talk to me.
Just keep talking to me.
The first man I ever
loved was my father.
He was strong and tall.
He carried me when
the ground was muddy.
He chased away
the monsters
that hid under
my bed at night.
And he sang to me
and kept me safe.
And he went away.
What I wouldn't give
to hear those songs again--
to feel his arms
protect me.
I never will.
But I can still feel
his warmth and his love
as though he were
here with me.
If you can feel
those things
from the man we know
as Will Riker,
accept them.
Accept the love.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44823.8:
Representatives of
the two moons of Peliar Zel
have agreed to come on board
to meet the "new"
Ambassador Odan.
White cell count
is elevated.
It's getting higher and higher
every time I read it.
Are you in pain?
Not much.
Ambassador, we can stall
the representatives.
They would see that
as a deception.
I must meet with them.
But surely, to present
yourself in this condition
is not going to
help our cause.
I promise you, Captain,
they will never know
that I'm ill.
Captain,
the emissaries.
May I present Kalin Trose
of Alpha Moon
and Lathal Bine
of Beta Moon.
Thank you
for receiving us, Captain.
Is this Ambassador Odan?
Lathal Bine,
it was your aunt who
represented Beta 30 years ago.
That is correct.
She was
a formidable woman.
I had the utmost respect
for her.
And who was it who spoke
for Alpha so long ago?
RIKER/ODAN:
That was you, of course--
Kalin Trose.
Then you were a young man,
bristling with
passion and zeal,
yet wise enough to understand
that your people needed peace
to ensure their future.
And how did you
achieve a compromise
between that young man
and the iron-willed woman
of Beta Moon?
They agreed to trade places
for a week
to understand
each other's situation
with more informed eyes.
After that,
an agreement came swiftly.
Nothing that you have said
is beyond what a schoolchild
could learn
in a history book.
What is not
commonly known is that,
during those negotiations,
you, Kalin Trose,
quelled a plot by
a radical from your own moon
who was attempting to
assassinate the Beta delegate.
It is true.
Perhaps he was wiser
in his youth
than he is now.
Odan, you must
convince him to stop.
Will you accept me?
Will you allow me
to work with you?
Yes.
And Alpha Moon?
I will consider it,
but I must consult others.
This is
a typical tactic.
He is an obstructionist.
You can see that.
Kalin Trose,
you may confer
with your people,
but we must have your answer
within eight hours.
You shall have it.
His vital signs
are overworked.
His immune system
is under attack.
I can only guess
that he's suffering
from classic
rejection syndrome.
Is there any treatment
you can give him?
I can administer
an immunosuppressant.
That could help relieve
the symptoms,
but it can't correct
the underlying cause.
There is a foreign
organism in his body.
Medical school didn't
exactly prepare me
for situations like this.
You're doing all you can.
Don't worry about me,
Captain, I'm fine.
Ambassador,
when you feel up to it,
would you join me
in my ready room?
Of course.
I can give you something
that should help with the pain,
at least for a little while.
The pain's gone.
Thank you.
Please don't.
Please let me touch you...
just for a moment.
No... please.
It was a fast decision,
which we must take as positive.
The Alphan representative
has agreed--
however reluctantly--
to let you
mediate the dispute.
I knew they would.
They're reasonable people.
They're just trapped
in their own anger.
I have no doubt, however,
that they will bolt
if something goes wrong
in the discussion.
Then it's my job to see
that nothing goes wrong.
Did I say something wrong,
Captain Picard?
No, it's just that...
for a moment, you sounded
more like Will Riker.
We have received
information
that the new host will
arrive in 18 hours.
Will you be all right
until then?
The medication Doctor Beverly
gave me has helped.
I will find a way
to keep going.
Lemon tea.
Computer, location
of Doctor Beverly Crusher.
COMPUTER: Doctor Crusher
is in her quarters.
Can you make balso tonic?
COMPUTER:
There is no formula on record.
Please supply
a molecular structure.
Never mind.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I thought I should see
how you were doing.
If you needed
another hypospray.
I don't think so.
The symptoms haven't returned.
Oh, well, that's good.
Yes.
Uh, tomorrow's
an important day.
Do you feel
ready for it?
I'll be fine.
I've been preparing.
Oh, that's good.
Yes.
I'll, um, check your
vital signs in the morning,
before the
representatives get here.
I don't want them knowing that
I'm taking any medication.
Maybe you could schedule
a series of breaks.
That's good.
Yes.
Beverly, I want you.
If you are going to leave,
you better go right now.
I'm not leaving.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44824.4:
Governor Leka
and the representatives
of the two moons are ready
to transport on board.
We have learned that
they each have troops massed
and are ready for combat,
if this final effort at peace
is not successful.
White count is back up.
Temperature is elevated.
The effects of
the medication
are wearing off
faster every time.
I'll administer one now
and hope that it will hold
for an hour or so.
No. No more.
Ambassador, it's clear
you're in pain.
You can't get through
the next hours without help.
I must.
Are the injections damaging to
the host's body, Riker's body?
Yes.
We can't put him
through any further risk.
But how can you function,
conduct the meeting?
I'll manage.
We'll respect your wishes.
One more thing--
I will conduct
the mediations today.
But at the end of today,
regardless of the outcome,
I must be removed
from Riker's body,
even if the new host
has not arrived.
But you won't survive.
Riker will not survive
if I am not removed.
He has done enough.
Your word.
Very well.
WORF:
Worf to Captain Picard.
Yes, Mr. Worf?
WORF: The Governor and the two
representatives have returned.
I will escort them
to the observation lounge.
PICARD:
Thank you.
( groans )
I'll stand by with
the medication, just in case.
The pain may become so intense
that I'll have to...
Beverly...
Whatever else I may be to you,
I'm your friend.
I can only imagine
what you're going through.
And I want you to know,
I'm here.
Jean-Luc.
Computer, what is the time?
COMPUTER: 1535 hours.
They've been in there
for almost six hours.
WORF:
Captain, I am receiving
a message from the ship
carrying the Trill host.
CRUSHER:
Are they here, Worf?
No, they are experiencing
difficulty.
They do not anticipate their
arrival for another nine hours.
Nine hours?
( door opening )
It was worth it.
Ambassador.
( sighs )
They will not go to war.
PICARD:
Mr. Worf, see that
the representatives
are safely transported
off the ship.
Ensign, set a course to
intercept with the Trill vessel.
Prepare to go to warp nine.
Sir, it could take more than
two hours to reach the vessel.
I must remove him.
I gave my word.
Will is going
to be all right.
His vital signs
have stabilized
and he's sleeping now.
How is Odan?
I've placed him
in stasis.
He's fine for the moment.
You need some rest, Doctor.
No.
If Odan is to survive,
he needs to be implanted
in the new host
as soon as he arrives.
I'll wait here.
It'll be some time.
I know.
Doctor.
Is the Trill host here?
Yes.
Good.
Bring him in.
Doctor?
I am Kareel.
I am to become host to Odan.
The operation to implant Odan
into the new host
was completed at 1900 hours
and appears
to have been successful.
There were no difficulties
in assimilation.
Doctor Beverly,
could we talk for a moment?
You should be sleeping.
You need to rest.
I've never felt better...
except once or twice.
My poor Beverly.
This has been
so hard for you.
I want to thank you
for your caring...
for your standing by me.
I congratulate you.
You averted a war that
would have cost many lives.
Yes.
It seems as though
everything has turned out
for the best.
And, yes, I am still Odan,
and I still love you.
I cannot imagine that
ever changing.
I am glad
that you're all right.
Is there to be nothing more?
Perhaps it is a human failing,
but we are not accustomed
to these kinds of changes.
I can't keep up.
How long will you have
this host?
What would
the next one be?
I can't live with that kind of
uncertainty.
( sighs )
Perhaps...
someday...
our ability to love
won't be so limited.
I understand.
Odan...
I do love you.
Please remember that.
I will never forget you.