Personal Log, Chief Engineer
Geordi La Forge,
Stardate 44885.5.
I am en route
to the planet Risa
to attend an artificial
intelligence seminar.
Captain Picard has ordered me
to arrive a few days early
to have some fun and relax.
I intend to follow
his orders to the very
best of my ability.
( classical music playing )
How about
some different music, Computer?
Something with a Latin beat.
( Latin jazz playing )
No, I meant something
with a gentle Latin beat.
Maybe a... a Spanish guitar.
( guitar playing )
( sighs )
Perfect.
Hey, what's the weather like
on Risa?
COMPUTER:
Risa is climate controlled
for optimum tourist comfort.
Is that right?
And about how long
till we get there?
Arrival at Risa is scheduled
for 0932 hours.
Ooh, three hours.
How about a game, Computer?
Please restate request.
Something to pass the time.
You know, a diversion.
Select either visual interactive
or verbal interactive.
Hmm... verbal.
You have 20 seconds to respond
to each question.
Level of difficulty
will increase as you progress.
Proceed when ready.
Begin.
List the resonances
of the sub-quantum states
associated with
transitional relativity...
That's easy.
...in alphabetical order.
Uh... well, uh...
a-asymmetrical...
uh, uh, uh, inverted...
um... uh, uh...
phased...
uh, stable...
Your time has expired.
( groans )
The fifth resonance is...
BOTH:
Universal.
I knew that.
Okay, okay.
Give me another one.
List the field patterns
associated with warp modulation
in order of decreasing energy.
Oh, okay. There's the aft
nacelle associative
the for...
Ho! Computer
sequence 0-1-0,
maximum power to the shields.
Kill the music.
Enterprise,
this is Shuttle Seven.
I've encountered
a Romulan warbird.
Coordinates are three...
COMPUTER:
Warning, shield failure.
Damn!
Risa Control.
Anybody!
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44891.6.
The Enterprise has
been ordered to accompany
a special emissary
from the Klingon High Council
to the Kriosian system
where one of their colonies
is fighting for independence.
There was a time when the Empire
would crush a rebellion.
Now it is tolerated.
We have enough troubles
on the home planet
so we don't wish
to divert resources
to such a trivial war.
You're preparing
to grant them independence?
Well, perhaps.
Conquer them again later,
if we wish.
PICARD:
May I ask,
Ambassador
what has this to do with us?
The Governor of Krios
has charged
that the Federation
is secretly aiding the rebels.
Does he have evidence?
The Council
has sent me here
to examine
that evidence.
It was my decision to invite you
to accompany me, Captain.
Many on the Council
have great respect for you.
K'adlo.
I have been pleased
to offer occasional assistance
to the Klingon people
in the past.
Your modesty is
very human, Captain.
I will excuse it.
But I can assure you,
Ambassador
that the Federation
would never interfere
in the internal affairs
of the Empire.
Let us hope not.
Such interference would strike
at the very basis
of our alliance.
Captain, we are in the war zone.
Indeed.
Ambassador, I will ask
our Chief Security Officer
Lieutenant Worf,
to make a report...
Uh, Captain
Worf's discommendation
makes that very awkward.
If I could work with one of
the other security officers...
Lieutenant Worf is
my Chief of Security
and my Tactical Officer.
This matter clearly falls
within his jurisdiction.
As you wish.
( grunts )
( door closes )
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, take it easy.
Hey!
( grunts )
Welcome, Mr. La Forge.
We've waited a long
time to meet you.
I can tell you've gone
to a lot of trouble.
Indeed, we have.
You are going to be
of great help to us.
Oh, I wouldn't
count on it.
Good. Very good.
Do not enjoy yourself
too much on Risa.
Hey!
Your VISOR
will be returned to you
but first, I want
to show you something.
Show me something?
That'll be a nice trick
seeing as how
I can't see anything
without the VISOR.
That is not quite true.
( groaning )
Allow me to demonstrate.
I now have direct access
to his visual cortex.
He has no choice but to see
what I wish him to see.
I can feed him
any image I choose.
He will be unable
to ignore it.
His galvanic skin response
has increased nine percent.
It seems Commander La Forge
like many humans,
has a low tolerance
for watching
others suffer.
( groans )
Why are you doing this?
I am sorry,
Commander.
It is a necessary step.
I apologize
for your discomfort.
Here.
Observe
how a spring day
on his native Earth
affects him.
He's looking
at a beautiful meadow--
green trees, birds,
a blue sky.
The heartbeat slows.
The galvanic skin
response drops.
The body responds
to our stimuli.
He is incapable
of maintaining control
of his own responses.
Watch as I change
the stimuli again.
Once our work is done,
La Forge will act normally
totally unaware
of his conditioning--
the perfect tool
for our purpose.
Will there be
any physical evidence
of what you're going
to do to him?
None, Commander.
That is why we chose La Forge.
The utilization of his
pre-existing neural implants
makes our work
impossible to detect.
How will we be certain your
procedure has been successful?
I will program him to perform
a series of specific tests
both before he leaves us
and after he returns
to the Enterprise.
We'll be able to verify
his effectiveness.
Notice that his heart rate
has slowed somewhat.
He is becoming
accustomed
to the horrors
he is witnessing.
So...
( grunts )
we change horrors.
( gasping )
( screaming )
There have been
two rebel attacks
on neutral freighters--
one the Ferengi,
and the other Cardassian.
Both were engaged
near the Ikanian asteroid belt.
That's where the
rebels must be hiding.
The actinides
in the asteroids
provide positive protection
against our sensors.
They might attack
a freighter
but I doubt they
would challenge a
Federation starship.
Especially with the Federation
furnishing them support.
You would test the Captain's
word with me, Kell?
Is it because I have
no honor in your eyes
that you expect me
to be disloyal?
Wrong of me to ask.
My apologies.
Captain Picard
does not lie.
If he says there is no
Federation assistance
to the rebels,
there is none.
Good. Because I risk
my own reputation
and honor coming to Picard.
He will not
disappoint you.
If that is all...
There are some members
of the High Council
who would thank you, Worf.
Thank me?
For killing Duras.
No doubt that, had he lived
one day, he would ascend
to head the Council.
Many were not
looking forward to that.
My motives were personal,
not political.
Motives?
Who cares for motives?
Humans, perhaps.
What matters is,
you acted on that day
as a true Klingon.
( quiet conversation )
Thanks.
So I've got to shut
the whole system down.
Where are we, Mr. La Forge?
This is Ten-Forward.
Who is that man
sitting over there?
LA FORGE:
That's Chief O'Brien.
How long has he
served with you?
Almost four years.
I want you to kill him.
Okay.
Take this phaser, and
kill Chief O'Brien.
Finally, I think
I've found it
when I see this piece of
conduit that's coded to be
the power linkage
to transporter seven.
Now, I know that
can't be right
so I give it a closer
look, and sure enough...
ROMULAN MAN:
Freeze simulation.
Commander, did you understand
my request?
Well, I...
It's just, I...
I don't...
Look at me.
Now, what did
I ask you to do?
Kill Chief O'Brien.
Then do as I asked.
Resume program.
O'BRIEN:
Well, you know
what that means.
Chief?
...'cause now, I have to...
( grunts )
Good, Mr. La Forge.
Very good.
Why don't you enjoy a drink
with your friends?
Mind if I join you guys?
Sure.
He still hesitated.
Prepare the equipment
for another session.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 44896.9.
We are orbiting Krios
awaiting our first meeting
with the Klingon Governor.
Commander La Forge
has rejoined the Enterprise
from Risa.
Welcome back, Geordi.
Data.
How was the seminar?
Very informative.
I'll tell you all about it.
It is fortunate we were
able to coordinate
your return on the
Teldarian cruiser.
Yeah. When I heard
the Enterprise
had been ordered
to the Krios system
I thought
I might be forced
to endure another couple
of weeks on Risa.
I am sorry to hear you
did not enjoy yourself.
I was joking.
Joking?
Ah. "Forced
to endure" Risa.
Your actual intent
was to emphasize that
you did enjoy yourself.
Yes, I see how that
could be considered
quite amusing.
( laughing ):
I missed you, Data.
Commander
La Forge.
Permission to come
aboard, Captain.
Granted.
Welcome back.
Thank you, sir.
Commander La Forge
is my Chief Engineer.
KELL:
Commander.
He's been attending a seminar
on artificial intelligence
on Risa.
I'm glad
we got you back, Geordi.
We're going to need
your help on this one.
LA FORGE:
Data tells me that
the Federation
has been accused
of aiding Kriosian rebels.
We're being presented
with evidence today.
We'll need your help
in analyzing it.
Anything I can do.
You had a good time.
Does it show?
You're more relaxed
than I've ever seen you.
Captain,
Governor Vagh has signaled.
He is ready to meet with you.
Very well. Advise him
that we will transport
down to the surface
immediately.
Ambassador.
Commander Riker?
What is it, Data?
Our sensors have detected
a brief energy fluctuation
in the E-band.
The E-band?
That's unusual.
What's the source?
Unknown, sir.
E-band emissions
are difficult to localize.
Collapsing protostars
sometimes emit
E-band bursts.
Yes, sir. However, there are
no protostars in this sector.
You better do
a complete scan.
Keep me posted.
Yes, sir.
...the Kanarians
who've actually done
the most advanced work
in artificial intelligence
so I spent a lot of time
in their research seminars.
Hmm. Geordi?
Hmm?
I get the feeling
that something special
happened on this vacation
and I'm not talking
about computers.
Well, I did take second place
in a chess tournament.
Yes?
( chuckles ):
And, uh, I swam a lot.
I worked on my backstroke.
The water is very calm on Risa.
And...?
And I walked a lot.
That's all.
Well, I ate enough
for 12 people.
The food there is terrific.
They've got a chocolate
there, Counselor,
that you would love.
And that's all?
Yeah.
Well, there was this...
Yes?
Her name is Jonic.
Ah.
But, uh...
you wouldn't want
to hear about that.
Better get ready
for duty.
Nice talking to you,
Counselor.
( door closes )
We talk, we socialize,
we waste time
and the insurrection
continues to grow.
These rebels need to
be crushed, not coddled.
Governor, it does not matter
what you or I think.
The High Council has made
its wishes clear.
The Council should be
more interested
in Federation interference.
Governor, exactly
what do you think
the Federation
has done?
Your medical supplies have been
found in rebel strongholds.
We make no effort
to restrict access to
our medical supplies.
Are your weapons
also freely available?
No, they are not.
Then explain this.
You took this weapon
from the rebels?
That and many more like it.
It does appear to be
Federation issue.
Governor, with your
permission I would like
to take this weapon back
to the Enterprise,
to verify its origin.
As you wish.
I have hundreds more.
But even if these weapons
are genuine
I can assure you that a third
party must have been involved.
The Federation is not
in the business
of supplying arms
to rebels.
This is the only Klingon colony
on the border
of Federation space.
You cannot deny
that Starfleet would be happy
to see Krios gain
its independence.
It would reduce
your vulnerability to an attack.
Governor, you speak as if
we are enemies and not allies.
And you speak the lies
of a tah-keck.
Qu'vath guy'cha b'aka.
Gentlemen...
You swear
well, Picard.
You must have Klingon
blood in your veins.
Governor, I will
report to you
as soon as the analysis
of that weapon is complete.
Captain, Commander.
Enterprise,
three to transport.
LA FORGE:
Intercooler flux
down to five percent.
Plasma deviation
steady at .72.
Aye, sir.
Well, you guys keep running
at this efficiency
I might as well go back to Risa
for another week.
Just run through
a level-4 series
and then call it a night, huh?
I'd help you,
but there's something
I've got to take care of.
Hi.
Red Torian, please.
Thank you.
Ooh!
Ah!
LA FORGE:
I'm sorry.
O'BRIEN:
It's all right.
My glass,
i-it just slipped.
It's nothing.
Just a little cold.
Yeah, but you're
all soaked here.
It's nothing serious.
Let me get something
to wipe it up.
No, no, I'll just go to
my quarters and change.
You're sure?
Don't think twice
about it, Commander.
Energy flow is within
normal parameters--
from the prefire chamber
to the emission aperture.
Rapid nadion pulse
is right on target.
Beam control assembly,
safety interlock--
both check out.
Beam width, intensity controls--
also responding correctly.
Energy cell usage
remains constant,
at 1.05 megajoules per second.
Curious.
The efficiency reading
on the discharge crystal
is well above
Starfleet specifications.
Yeah, by quite a bit.
94.1% efficiency.
Our most efficient
discharge crystal
typically fires
with 86.5% efficiency.
Hmm. Let's take a closer look
at the wave pattern
on the emission beam.
That might tell us why
it's losing so little energy.
Pulse frequency out
of prefire chamber
reads steady.
There. That's not right.
The initial output spike
is inverted.
That might suggest
the weapon has been charged
with a forced pulse
well into the terahertz range.
Then it's definitely
not Starfleet issue
and there can't be
that many systems
that use the terahertz feeds.
327, to our knowledge.
We can probably
achieve an
exact match
with a random
computer search.
It will take
approximately
three hours.
I think
we can narrow this down
with a little common sense,
Data.
Who has the most to gain
from a conflict
between the Klingon Empire
and the Federation?
The Romulans.
They fashioned
the perfect Federation rifle
but they had to charge it
from their own energy sources.
So the discharge crystal
and the emission beam pattern
both correspond
to those you'd find
in a Romulan disrupter.
The Romulans
have no interest
in Kriosian
independence.
This planet is
too far from
their borders.
PICARD:
But they do have
an interest
in driving the
Federation and
the Empire apart.
Our alliance is the
only thing that has
kept them in check.
VAGH:
Romulan replications
using stolen
Federation technology?
It's a typical Romulan ploy--
an attempt to sow dissension
and mistrust.
Commander,
you've done very well.
I would thank you
on behalf
of the Empire.
I still have my
doubts, Picard.
I will want my
own technicians
to confirm
your findings.
Of course.
My staff will give you
their full cooperation.
You may go.
RIKER:
Another E-band blip?
Yes, sir. However the
difference in intensity
indicates this one
did not originate
in the same location
as the first.
If it's changed intensity
it can't possibly
be a protostar.
That is
a reasonable assumption.
Is there any
known instance
of the Romulans
using E-band for
communications?
Not to my knowledge, sir.
Can you track
the source?
We can reconfigure
the primary sensor array.
If we narrow their focus
to scan for E-band emissions
We might be able to calculate
a directional vector
but only if there
are more occurrences.
Do it.
Computer, reroute the power flow
in the Cargo Bay Four
transporter
through the auxiliary
replicator system.
COMPUTER:
Please verify command
with necessary protocol.
Initiate protocol 364-B.
Verify priority clearance.
Recognize La Forge,
theta-2-9-9-7.
Acknowledged.
Power has been rerouted
through auxiliary power
distribution system.
Code number 4-4-7-6-2.
Now, redirect transporter mode
to the planetary sensor array.
Transporter mode
has been redirected.
Verify that all record
of these modifications
are being erased
from each directory.
Affirmative.
Erasure process is proceeding.
Sir, we are being hailed
by Governor Vagh.
On screen,
Mr. Worf.
Governor.
You astonish me, Picard.
Did you seriously believe
you would succeed?
Do you think we are blind?
I don't understand.
We intercepted the weapons
you tried to transport
to the surface.
Governor, I assure you...
Do not insult us both
by denying it.
Maintain your position
until further notice.
Do not attempt to leave orbit.
Klingon attack cruiser
uncloaking, sir.
PICARD:
On screen.
Two birds of prey approaching.
Sensors confirm an unauthorized
transporter beam at 1123 hours.
Do you know which
transporter was used?
I'm not sure, Captain.
Whoever did it apparently
used the planetary array
to bypass
the transport sensors.
What about
the transporter logs?
They're blank.
How many people
on board
are capable
of this, Geordi?
I'm not even sure
how it was done yet.
As soon as I find out,
maybe I can give you an answer.
Not many,
that's for sure.
Vagh is fully prepared
to open fire on the Enterprise.
I've convinced him
it would not be wise
to take any action
without first consulting
the High Council.
How long do we have?
A few hours,
at most.
Mr. La Forge, your
recommendations?
Well, it might be possible
to locate the point of origin
by tracing power flows
at the time of transport.
Make it so.
DATA:
The primary plasma system
does not indicate
a power drain
from any
of the transporters.
Then whoever
used the transporter
must have bypassed
the primary feeds.
Tracking power from
the secondary systems.
No surges to any
of the transporters indicated.
Damn.
Who could have
pulled this off?
Try the life-support
power flows.
No abnormal surges
indicated.
Replicator wave guides?
There.
That's not
a replicator
energy pattern.
Trace it.
Cargo Bay Four.
La Forge to Worf.
Security to Cargo Bay Four.
I've run a level-1 diagnostic.
As far as I can tell
the unit hasn't
been tampered with.
This has to be
the transfer point.
Perhaps the perpetrator
reprogrammed
the memory chips
to erase any record.
You're talking about
30 or 40 chips
in half a dozen
different control systems.
Which members of
the crew could have
accomplished that?
I think I could have done it,
if I put my mind to it.
The Chief, Data,
Lieutenant Costa.
That's about it.
Procedure requires
that I ask each of you
where you were
at 1123 hours.
Well, I was with Keiko...
in the arboretum.
DATA:
I was on the Bridge
at my station.
I was in my quarters.
WORF:
Was anyone
with you?
No, I was alone.
And Costa was on duty
in Engineering.
I'm sure he's got
20 witnesses.
Then there is someone
on board who isn't
what he or she
seems to be.
Data, let's do
a detailed scan
on every chip
in this assembly.
There's got to
be some kind
of trail we can follow.
The isolinear chips
were definitely altered?
Programmed
to erase all
operator commands
once the transfer
was complete.
But with the chips erased,
what evidence remains?
The erasures
were complete.
However,
an analysis
of the subatomic
structure
revealed an almost
undetectable
residual pattern.
In time, we may be
able to reconstruct
the perpetrator's
authorization code.
You have any idea
who's responsible?
LA FORGE:
No, sir.
Everyone
with the necessary skills
also has an alibi.
Except for me,
that is.
I was alone in my
quarters at the time.
Then whoever did this
must have been
specially trained
for the task.
PICARD:
Our forensic team
is trying
to identify anyone
who might have been
in Cargo Bay Four today.
It's not going to be easy.
There were a lot of people
in and out of there.
Riker to Data.
Yes, Commander.
Sensors have picked up
another E-band emission.
Acknowledged.
I will be there shortly.
E-band emission?
We have been picking up
a curious intermittent blip.
Commander Riker has speculated
that it might be
a Romulan transmission.
I am attempting to track
its source.
Proceed.
Thank you, Mr. La Forge.
We do not have
much time, Picard.
Vagh is not noted
for his patience.
Assure him that we are
doing everything possible
and advise him that,
if necessary
I will defend my ship.
With your permission
I will transport
down to the planet.
Of course.
May I suggest
that you issue
an invitation
to Governor Vagh
to personally witness
your ongoing investigation.
Do you think he will come?
I will do everything in my power
to see that he does.
Qapla', Picard.
Qapla', Ambassador.
( chuckles )
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Come in, Mr. La Forge.
The investigation is moving
faster than we expected.
You're in danger
of being exposed.
I will transport
to the surface
and when I return
I'll have Governor Vagh
with me.
Your Captain and I will
bring him to the cargo bay.
I want you to kill him there,
in front of many witnesses.
Use a hand phaser.
When he is dead
you will claim
that you acted
on behalf of Starfleet
in support
of Kriosian independence.
I understand.
Mmm.
( sighs )
( moans softly )
( moans loudly )
( gasps )
La Forge to O'Brien.
O'Brien?
Go ahead, Commander.
What can I do for you?
Uh...
nothing.
Chief, I'm...
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I'm sorry.
( sighs )
LA FORGE:
Hiya, Doc.
Geordi, hi.
What can I do for you?
Well, I just can't seem
to get any sleep.
I was hoping you could
give me something.
Sit down.
Let's take a look.
You couldn't
sleep at all?
No, I was restless.
I kept waking up.
Hmm. Would you take
off your VISOR, please?
Sure.
Is there something
on your mind?
No, I don't think so.
Well, everybody
goes through
these occasional
bouts of insomnia.
There's probably
nothing to worry about.
Let's just make sure that
there's nothing
physically wrong.
There's a minor
vascular irregularity
in the visual cortex.
A slight dilation
of the blood vessels.
It's nothing serious.
What about your VISOR?
Has it been giving you
any problems lately?
Nothing out of the ordinary.
All the same, it might be a
good idea to have it examined
when we get to
Starbase 36 next month.
Okay.
In the meantime,
I will get you
a somnetic inducer
to put by your bed.
It will help
you to sleep.
Thanks, Doc.
I'm sure I'll be fine.
Energize.
Governor Vagh,
thank you for coming.
You can thank
Ambassador Kell.
I am here against
my better judgment.
Captain, I think
the first thing
the Governor should see
is the investigation
underway in
the cargo bay.
Of course.
RIKER:
From inside the Enterprise?
You're sure?
DATA:
The first and third
E-band blips
were clearly generated
on board the ship.
The second came from
the planet's surface.
Generated by what?
Unknown, sir.
Mr. Data, we have
a known spy on board.
And now we have unexplained
signals on board.
I think it's reasonable
to assume
that they're related somehow,
don't you?
One could speculate
that the E-band
was being used as some form
of covert communication.
We need more than speculation,
Mr. Data.
We need to know who, what,
where, when and why
or we may be going to war.
Yes, sir.
Computer, run an analysis
of all known Romulan
transmission formats.
All bands.
Identify any commonalties
with displayed waveform.
No commonalties noted.
Does this waveform match that
of any known
communication format?
Negative.
Broaden search pattern
beyond communications.
Does the waveform displayed
conform to any natural phenomena
cryptographic formats,
or life-form EM emissions?
The signal corresponds
to a delta-compressed
wavelength spectrum
similar to human
neural frequencies.
As in a human
brain wave pattern?
Affirmative.
What kind of receiver
would be capable
of processing these signals?
A system designed to modify
the electromagnetic spectrum
and carry those messages
directly to the human brain.
Computer, link with
the shuttle's onboard system.
Access the isolinear
storage assembly.
Scan all chips
which contain mission logs.
Note any discrepancies.
No discrepancies noted.
Perform a level-5 diagnostic
on the shuttle's navigational
and power systems.
The components specified are
all within normal tolerances.
O'BRIEN:
My technicians
have examined
all of the ship's
transporters, sir.
I can assure you,
this is the only unit
that has been
tampered with.
Computer, scan the shuttle's
structural integrity.
Sub-microscopic deformations
are present
in the nose section
and aft thrusters.
Probable cause
of these variations?
The shuttle has been subjected
to stress consistent
with a tractor beam.
( indistinct voices )
PICARD ( indistinctly ):
All of our transporter
rotators are produced
with a slight... in
the structural alloys
which allow us
to trace our
material back
to the exact...
It also gives us an
identifiable matter...
O'BRIEN:
Commander La Forge.
What can I do
for you, Chief?
Could you look
at the pattern buffers?
Considering what's happened
I'm not sure the control systems
are reliable.
( Picard continues indistinctly)
Sure, sure.
Let's take a look.
Computer, I am reading
anomalous variations
in the molecular structure
of these memory chips.
Please confirm.
Analysis confirmed.
Probable cause?
Replication.
Compare these variations
with established Romulan
replication patterns.
The patterns are identical.
Then maybe we should run
a level-1 diagnostic
on those phase
transition coils.
Right, Commander.
PICARD:
I'm still confident...
Data to La Forge.
Report, please.
Geordi.
Please respond.
Computer, current location
of Commander La Forge.
Cargo Bay Four.
Data to Lieutenant Worf.
Priority One.
Go ahead.
Take Commander La Forge
into custody immediately.
Sir?
That is an order.
PICARD:
We've been looking
for DNA samples.
By tracing
the biochemical signatures
they will be able
to determine
who was in this bay
recently.
VAGH:
But how will it be possible
to prove which one...
Q'ac Ken ta'vak!
La Forge!
Mr. Worf, get
him out of here.
Arming our enemies
is not enough.
Now the Federation would
murder me to achieve its aims.
Governor, if I could
explain this, I would.
I believe I can help,
Captain.
I've been able to determine
that Commander La Forge
was abducted by Romulans
en route to Risa.
It is likely that he was
somehow forced
to take part
in the plot
to assassinate
Governor Vagh.
I saw no evidence
of Romulans.
We just witnessed him
acting very much alone.
No, sir, you did not.
I do not believe
the Commander
is acting
of his own accord.
He has been receiving
E-band signals
through his VISOR--
signals which
are carrying
direct commands
to his brain.
I have surmised
that Commander La Forge
was conditioned by Romulans
a process
referred to
historically--
and somewhat inaccurately--
as "brainwashing."
VAGH:
But to what end?
Why would the Romulans
want to kill me?
The Romulans have always wanted
to destroy the alliance
between the Federation
and the Klingons.
If Mr. La Forge
had killed you, Governor
I think
you would agree
they might have
succeeded.
Who sent these signals?
A cloaked Romulan ship?
DATA:
No, sir.
That is not possible.
The signals had
to be transmitted
within close proximity
to the VISOR.
Are you suggesting
that there was
a Romulan accomplice
in close proximity
to Mr. La Forge when he
was receiving the signals?
Yes, sir, I am.
VAGH:
This Romulan
accomplice
who is he?
I have narrowed the list
of possibilities
to two people--
the only two people
who were with
Commander La Forge
all three times
a transmission
was recorded--
Captain Picard
and Ambassador Kell.
One of them
may be concealing
an E-band transmitter.
If they would agree
to be searched...
I am a Klingon,
an emissary of the High Council.
I will not submit
to being searched
by you or anyone else
on this ship.
VAGH:
I am forced to
agree, Captain.
We will take the Ambassador
with us
and search him ourselves.
Captain, I believe it to be
in all our best interests
if I remain aboard.
I formally request asylum.
I will certainly
grant you asylum...
when you have been absolved
of this crime.
Gurt'ank te'la.
But I remember everything!
Like, there was this one night
at dinner.
We had this Andorian waiter.
He couldn't get
our orders right.
It did happen!
I remember
being on Risa.
I know you do.
Just take that memory
and put it aside for a moment
and tell me
everything you remember
about the shuttlecraft trip
after you left the Enterprise.
( sighs )
Well, I... I was just trying
to get in the mood.
I, uh...
I played some music.
I talked to the computer.
You know what it's like
on a long trip.
And when you saw
the Romulan ship
did you try and call for help?
No, the first thing I did...
Wait a minute.
That...
But that's...
It'll take time, Geordi.
A long time.
But we will reconstruct
your memory...
together.
I'm just not sure...
about anything.
Believe it or not,
that's a good sign.
A beginning.
Now, let's go back
to the shuttlecraft.
There was a Romulan ship
and the first thing
you did was...?