Captain's Log,
Stardate 44932.3:
The Enterprise is preparing
to enter the Mar Oscura,
an unexplored
dark matter nebula.
Commander Data is modifying
several of our photon torpedoes
for an experiment designed
to elicit more information
about this unusual phenomenon.
The initial dispersal pattern
should not be more
than seven kilometers
in diameter.
Jenna?
Oh. Uh, 6.8 kilometers.
That should suffice.
Is there something occupying
your thoughts, Jenna?
You seem somewhat
subdued today.
I bumped into Jeff again
in the turbolift this morning.
He asked me
out to dinner.
What was your response?
I told him
I'd think about it.
As you requested,
I will now remind you
of the reasons you decided to
end your relationship with Jeff.
I guess I asked for this.
Go ahead.
You objected to the fact
that he seemed unwilling
to set aside
sufficient time for you.
You said he was
unresponsive,
that he never did
the little things.
You disliked the sound he made
when he ate his soup.
Okay, okay. I remember.
This is the third time
I have refreshed your memory.
Do you wish to rescind
our agreement?
No. No, it's
for my own good.
It's just so easy
to forget.
Hand me the sequencer.
Throughout history,
many lovers have suffered
the same difficulty.
Anne Boleyn was quite distressed
that Henry the VIII
preferred the company of his
huntsmen over that of his wife.
Since when did you
develop an interest
in romantic
historical figures?
Six weeks ago, when you and Jeff
dissolved your relationship,
I saw an excellent opportunity
to study that aspect
of human intimacy.
As your friend,
it is my responsibility
to be supportive
in times of need.
That's, uh...
that's very sweet, Data.
Data to Bridge.
We are ready to begin
the first illumination test.
Acknowledged.
All science stations stand by.
We're about to light up
the nebula. Mr. Worf?
Launch Bay One
shows ready, Commander.
Fire torpedo.
Jenna:
It's beautiful.
Like watching fireworks
when I was a little girl.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( playing Reicha's "Woodwind
Quintet in E-flat major" )
That was wonderful.
Really?
Really. Wonderful.
Thanks.
Is something wrong?
My tempo was way off.
I felt like I was rushing
through the whole piece.
I do not believe
that is so.
Your rhythmic control
has improved markedly.
I heard no fluctuations
during the performance.
Well, maybe,
but I ruined the coda.
I got confused
with the phrasing again.
I kept breathing
at the wrong times.
The contrapuntal nature of the
composition is most demanding.
We will give more attention
to the rhythmic patterns
during our next rehearsal.
However, I am quite certain
the audience was oblivious
to such nuances.
They seemed to enjoy
the performance thoroughly.
Thank you, Data.
You're very generous.
KEIKO:
Every night, Miles leaves
his socks on the floor.
When we got married,
I made the mistake of
picking them up a few times.
Then I realized,
if I kept it up,
I'd be doing it
for the rest of my life.
So I stopped,
figuring he'd get the point
and do it himself.
One night goes by...
two... a week...
ten days.
By now there's a pile of socks
half a meter high.
Oh, come on,
it wasn't half a meter.
After two weeks,
I couldn't stand it anymore.
I bundled them up and put them
in the cleaning processor.
And I'm still doing it.
And a very good job
she does of it, too.
Keiko, you sound
just like Data.
He came over to my quarters
the other day to give me
a music lesson
and he said
the funniest thing.
How did you put it?
About the mess?
I believe I observed
that you seem to have
an aversion to orderliness.
But it was not intended
as a humorous remark.
So, before we started,
he gallantly offered
to help me straighten up.
And a very good job
I did of it, too.
Report, Mr. Data.
I have nearly finished
compiling readings
of our most recent
illuminatory burst.
Dark matter density
is nearly one order of
magnitude higher
than in similar nebulae.
Life-forms may have developed
in ways never before observed.
Interesting hypothesis.
Are there any M Class planets
we can check out?
Several, sir.
The nearest is approximately
three light-hours from
our present position.
It's worth a look.
We'll continue
our survey along the way.
Let's increase the flow rate
and see if that helps.
( metallic clink )
Sometimes in the summer,
we'd go on cookouts--
just my little brother
and me and my mother.
She was hopeless
without a replicator,
we didn't care.
Children often
do not develop
discerning palettes until
well beyond adolescence.
It wasn't that.
It's just that we felt
so good being together,
you know, as a family.
We didn't have much of that
after my father died,
so those times
were really special.
I wish we were
back there now, you and I.
The unidirectional nature
of the time continuum
makes that
an unlikely possibility.
That's what I love about you,
Data, you make me laugh.
I don't know why I keep falling
for the wrong men.
Why can't I fall for
somebody like you?
You're perfect.
That is not true.
I have no human feelings.
But you give me so much.
You spend time with me
when I'm lonely.
You encourage me
when I'm down.
No man has ever
been kinder to me.
Those are the things
that matter.
I better be going.
With your permission,
Commander.
Permission granted.
I don't know
if you're aware of this,
but you're very handsome.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hello, Data.
Would you like
to try something new?
It's a concoction
I heard about on Prakal II.
I think it's wonderful,
but I need a second opinion.
87% Saurian brandy.
Targ milk and Denevian mead
comprise the rest.
There is an unusually
high concentration
of fructose compound
and monosaccharides.
Too sweet?
Data, if I didn't
know you better,
I would say you were
a little... preoccupied.
Lieutenant D'Sora
just gave me
what could be considered
a very passionate kiss
in the Torpedo Bay.
Really?
And...
I was intrigued.
Jenna seemed to be displaying
genuine affection for me.
Well...
what do you think
of her, Data?
I find her to be
a competent officer,
highly motivated,
though, somewhat lacking
in her understanding
of the theory underlying
the dilithium matrix
application.
I meant personally.
I look forward to the time
we spend together.
Well, then it seems
the next move is yours.
What are you going to do?
I do not know.
I have no experience
in such matters.
I require advice.
Don't look at me.
No, no, Data.
I simply mean
that I can't give you
any advice here.
It's not good to advise people
about their first love affairs.
That's kind of something
people have to figure out
for themselves.
But I am not capable of love.
Then it's going to be
a very unique experience.
Data?
Missing someone?
I found Spot wandering
through the corridor
two sections away.
Thank you.
Forget to secure
the door when you left?
The door sensor
is programmed
to recognize only humanoid forms
per entrance and egress.
Spot could not have
triggered the mechanism.
Maybe somebody came in
while you were away.
Let him out
by accident.
Has anything
been disturbed?
It does not
appear so.
Computer, has anyone
been in my quarters
in the last 12 hours other than
Commander La Forge or myself?
COMPUTER:
Negative.
That's pretty strange.
You know, to be on the safe
side, maybe I should report
a possible unauthorized
entry to Security.
Geordi, may I ask
your advice...
in a personal matter?
Sure, Data.
Should I pursue a relationship
with Lieutenant D'Sora?
I thought she
and Jeff Arton...
They have discontinued
their association.
She has made
the first move in initiating
a relationship with me.
What should I do?
( sighs )
Boy.
If she's just coming out
of a bad situation...
you know, sometimes
it takes people a while, Data.
But then, if they jump right
into another relationship...
you see that can be trouble.
Unless, of course,
she's really ready and then...
well, I guess it
depends on whether or not
you're really serious.
This can be
a little complicated.
Listen, my advice is...
ask somebody else
for advice.
At least someone
who's got more experience
at giving advice.
I think you should be careful.
This isn't just some experiment
you're running, Data.
Jenna is a living,
breathing person
with needs and feelings
that have to be considered.
Then you do not believe I should
pursue this any further.
I didn't say that.
I just want you to be aware
that this is
unlike any other
more casual relationship
that you've attempted.
I have studied
much human literature
on the subject of love
and romantic liaisons.
There are many role models
for me to emulate.
Ultimately, Jenna will
care for you for who you are,
not what you imitate
out of a book.
My programming may be
inadequate to the task.
We're all more than the sum
of our parts, Data.
You'll have to be more
than the sum
of your programming.
Klingons do not
pursue relationships.
They conquer that
which they desire.
However...
Lieutenant D'Sora
serves under my command.
If she were mistreated,
I would be
very displeased...
sir.
I understand.
I think you should pursue it.
First of all,
she's a beautiful woman.
She seems to be
crazy about you.
Jenna has clearly demonstrated
how she feels about me,
but I am not capable
of returning those feelings.
Data...
when you get involved
with another person,
there are always risks--
of disappointment,
of getting hurt.
I cannot be hurt,
but she can.
Jenna knows that
and she has obviously decided
to take the chance.
Data, when it really works
between two people,
it's not like anything
you've ever experienced.
The rewards are far greater
than simple friendship.
How far, sir?
That's what I'm hoping
you're going to find out.
Captain?
I am seeking advice
in how to...
Yes, I've heard, Data.
And I will be delighted
to offer any advice I can
on understanding women.
When I have some,
I'll let you know.
Second Officer's
Personal Log,
Stardate 44935.6:
After conferring
with my colleagues
regarding the nature
of romantic love in general,
and my own situation
in particular,
I have reached a decision.
Oh, they're lovely.
Come in.
What are they?
A variety of crystilia.
Their fragrance is
an evolutionary response
to the acrid nature of the
atmosphere on Telemarius IV.
You silver-tongued devil.
Um, why don't I find
a place to put these...
which won't be that easy.
Ah.
It seems your quarters
have reverted
to their earlier state
of disorder.
I know. I'm hopeless.
There.
They're beautiful, Data.
It's really sweet of you.
Commander Riker suggested
this particular flower.
He said it had worked
for him in the past.
You didn't talk
to the entire ship about us?
No. In actuality,
less than one percent
of the Enterprise crew
was involved.
Huh.
It was necessary
to balance theory
with experiential
referents.
Both are required for
a program of this nature.
Computer,
decrease illumination level
by one-third standard lux.
Uh, this is all part
of a program?
Yes, one which I just created
for romantic relationships.
So I'm, uh,
I'm just a small variable
in one of your new
computational environments?
You are much more
than that, Jenna.
I have written a subroutine
specifically for you--
a program
within the program.
I have devoted a considerable
share of my internal resources
to its development.
Data...
that's the nicest thing
anybody's ever said to me.
Estimated time
of arrival, Mr. Data.
We will reach
the Class M planet
in approximately
11 hours, sir.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Yes, Captain.
PICARD: Would you step into
my ready room, please?
And bring a tricorder
with you.
Aye, Captain.
Captain?
What do you make of this?
I am puzzled, sir.
So am I, Mr. Worf.
The only detectable bioelectric
residuals are your own.
You did not...
No, I did not.
Well, perhaps we have
a poltergeist.
Sir?
A mischievous spirit.
Sir.
Perhaps not.
I cannot explain how
an intruder entered this room.
But I recommend
we go to red alert.
Not yet.
Then I will order one of
my officers to stand watch.
Worf to Ensign--
That's all right,
Mr. Worf.
I think, for now,
circumstances
warrant caution,
nothing more.
As you wish, Captain.
( door chimes )
Enter.
I know it's
a little unexpected.
You are correct.
I did not anticipate
your arrival until 1900 hours.
Well, I couldn't wait.
Um, I wanted you
to have this.
You have often expressed
dissatisfaction
with the spartan nature
of my quarters.
Is this an attempt
at embellishment?
The cat's out of the bag.
Spot?
No, I mean you've
caught me in the act.
I'm just trying to brighten
things up around here.
It's Tyrinean.
What do you think?
Its line is both fluid
and formal,
yet retains
an unpremeditated quality.
The tactility of its surface
embellishment is evocative
of the neo-primitive period
in Tyrinean blade carving.
Um, I hadn't thought of it
in that way.
I'm sorry.
Don't let me interrupt.
As you wish.
Uh, Data?
Yes?
The book of love,
chapter four, paragraph 17--
when your girlfriend
arrives with a gift,
stop whatever it is
you're doing
and give her your
undivided attention.
I should not have resumed
my painting.
No.
Despite your suggestion
that I continue.
Exactly.
I have much to learn.
Um, why don't we start
with this?
A critical analysis
isn't necessarily
the best response
to a gift.
Perhaps if I looked for
a suitable place to display it.
Much better.
The ambient light
in this location
accentuates its contours.
However...
a gift should not
necessarily be placed
according to
aesthetic criteria.
A more central location
would give added meaning.
Data, what's important
is that you're trying.
You don't know how much
that means to me.
Why don't you go back
to your painting?
Oh, I really mean it
this time.
I'll see you tonight.
RIKER:
Riker to Captain Picard.
I think you'd better
come out here, sir.
Acknowledged.
We've reached
the designated coordinates,
but the M Class planet...
it's gone.
Are you sure there was
no malfunction in the sensors?
The lateral E-M scanners
register radiation levels
indicative of
a Class M planet.
Sir...
Mr. Data, run a full
systems diagnostic.
COMPUTER: Warning--
atmospheric decompression
in Bridge
observation lounge.
Environmental compensation
sequence has been initiated.
I am not registering
a hull breach.
Scan for life-forms.
None, sir.
Captain,
standard air pressure
has been reestablished
in the observation lounge.
Let's have a look.
Mr. Data?
Captain.
WORF:
I do not understand.
Are you picking
anything up, Data?
I detect no unusual readings
along standard parameters.
Curious.
The transparent aluminum
alloy of this window
is exhibiting a pattern
of transient
electrical currents.
Explanation.
I have none.
The rate is characteristic
of a subspace distortion,
but I am picking up no evidence
of a subspace field.
We'll hold position
while we seek an explanation
of these anomalies.
Let's divert all
our resources to that end.
Honey, I'm home.
Hi.
Any luck with
your diagnostic?
Negative.
We found no malfunctions.
We did a full
security sweep.
Nothing.
May I...
get you a drink, dear?
Well, yes.
I'll... I'll have
a Calaman sherry.
Excellent choice.
I'll join you.
Computer, two...
Calaman sherries.
Would you care for
some dinner as well?
Oh, I'm too tired to
think about what I want.
Maybe later.
Whatever you wish, dear.
There we are.
Uh-uh...
Darling,
you remain
as aesthetically pleasing
as the first day we met.
I believe I am
the most fortunate sentient
in this sector
of the galaxy.
You...
relax...
put your feet up...
and I will take care
of everything.
( singing aria from La Boheme )
I could organize
your closets for you.
I have found
that by grouping apparel,
first by function, then by
color, from light to dark,
one can more easily find
one's desired choice.
Uh, Data...
that's all right.
You don't have to do that.
But I am happy to do it.
Please, just put them down.
( shoes dropping )
What do you wish me to do, dear?
Am I not paying
enough attention to you?
Oh, no, that's not it, um...
Perhaps I am not giving you
enough compliments.
Your hair...
is looking particularly
silky tonight.
Data, there's just
something strange
about the way
you're acting.
Am I not behaving
as a solicitous mate?
Well, yes, but...
Tending to
your every need?
What's wrong
with you tonight?
My most recent self-diagnostic
revealed no malfunctions.
Perhaps there is something
wrong with you!
I've never seen you
behave so foolishly.
Why are you doing this?
You don't tell me how to behave.
You're not my mother!
What?
You are not my mother.
That is the appropriate
response for your statement
that I am behaving foolishly.
Data, I think you
should just leave.
You do not wish to continue
our lovers' quarrel?
Is that what this is?
In my study of
interpersonal dynamics,
I have found that conflict,
followed by emotional release
often strengthens the connection
between two people.
But there's
something so forced
and artificial about the way
you're doing it, Data.
It's just not
the real you.
With regard to
romantic relationships,
there is no real me.
I am drawing upon various
cultural and literary sources
to help define my role.
Kiss me.
What were you
just thinking?
In that particular moment,
I was reconfiguring
the warp field parameters,
analyzing the collective works
of Charles Dickens,
calculating
the maximum pressure
I could safely apply
to your lips,
considering a food
supplement for Spot...
I'm glad I was
in there somewhere.
A complete sensor scan
of the planet
and three survey probes
came up with no surprises.
No signs of life.
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Seven more unusual incidents
have been reported.
No casualties or damage.
We can only state
that a subspace effect
seems to exist
within this nebula.
After I have made further
analysis,
I may be able to adjust
the ship's sensors to locate
and identify the anomaly.
RIKER: The ship's at risk
as long as we're sitting here.
We could continue
the investigation
outside the nebula.
Agreed.
Ensign McKnight, plot the most
direct course ahead warp one.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
DATA:
Captain...
Captain, explosive
decompression on Deck 37.
Bridge to La Forge.
Damage report.
We're showing damage
between decks.
We haven't localized it yet.
( moaning )
Thorne, are you all right?
Yes, sir.
La Forge to Bridge.
A cryogenic control conduit
just blew out on us.
I almost lost a man.
Ensign, full stop.
Aye, sir.
LA FORGE: La Forge to Bridge.
Go ahead, Commander.
LA FORGE:
I think we have some structural
damage between Decks 36 and 37.
I'd better go check it out.
Van Mayter,
you take access tube 23 M
and look at those
Bridge connectors.
Thorne, I'll cover
the aft section.
You go down...
( woman screams )
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
This series of
unexplained events
has now resulted
in the death of a crewman.
But it appears Mr. Data
may have an explanation.
DATA:
During the last occurrence,
I was able to confirm
one of my hypotheses.
The unusual preponderance
of dark matter in this nebula
is causing small gaps
in the fabric of normal space.
As the Enterprise moves
through this nebula,
it is colliding
with these deformations.
So every time
we hit one,
part of the ship momentarily
phases out of normal space.
Or when one of them hits us.
My readings suggest that
the deformations are in motion.
It's a good thing
one of those pockets
didn't pass through
the photon torpedo casings.
Or one of the matter/anti-matter
containment pods.
The question is
how do we get out?
Mr. Data, could you
reconfigure the sensors
so as to detect
these anomalies?
Yes, sir, but only
at extremely close range.
Even at minimal speed,
it would be impossible
to maneuver the Enterprise
quickly enough to avoid them.
A shuttlecraft is
more maneuverable.
He's right.
If we could position
the shuttlecraft
far enough in front
of the Enterprise,
it could detect the pockets
and allow us enough time to
maneuver out of the way.
We could give the shuttle
control of our navigational
systems.
That way
the corresponding maneuvers
would be virtually
instantaneous.
Make it so.
RIKER:
I'll do my pre-flight
once I'm on board.
Not this time, Will.
I want you on the Bridge.
Sir?
I'm going to pilot
the shuttle.
Captain, it is my duty
as First Officer
to safeguard the lives
on this ship, including yours.
The Enterprise can't
afford to lose you,
certainly not
in this situation.
I believe our best chance of
escaping this situation
is for me to pilot
the shuttle.
It's my ship, Will.
I've got to do this.
Sir.
Shuttle three to Enterprise.
Telemetry link enabled.
DATA:
Ship's computer is accepting
navigational inputs
from the shuttle.
Forward sensors are online.
Ensign McKnight,
plot a course
for the shortest distance
out of the nebula.
McKNIGHT:
Plot laid in, sir.
Outer perimeter
at 32 million kilometers.
PICARD:
Point one impulse, Number One.
Acknowledged, Captain,
We're right behind you.
Riker to O'Brien, lock on to
the Captain's communicator.
I want to be able to pull him
out of there in case we have to.
Aye, sir.
Changing course.
New heading, 299.029.
Main coupling is matching
navigational inputs, Captain.
New heading confirmed.
I missed it by less than
1,000 meters, Enterprise.
Advise your status.
Sensors indicate deformation
passing 500 meters
off the starboard bow.
One down, Captain.
Resuming previous course.
McKNIGHT:
Confirmed.
Outer perimeter now at
30.1 million kilometers.
Changing course.
Heading 073.288.
New heading, 284.01--
Enterprise,
I'm losing maneuverability.
Sensors indicate damage
to the shuttle's
starboard impulse nacelle.
I'm re-routing the secondary
deuterium supply.
Switching to manual control.
Transceiver signal
is down 42%.
Navigational inputs
are not registering.
We've lost our link, Captain.
You'll have to make course
changes manually
until we reestablish
the connection.
Understood.
Mr. Data, get us back online.
Geordi, boosting
the power to the L-U bands.
McKnight,
increase the distance
between the Enterprise
and the shuttle.
We're going to need some more
room to make manual adjustments.
New heading, 299.18.
McKNIGHT: Yes, sir, I've got it.
Course corrected.
Enterprise, hard starboard!
McKNIGHT:
Aye, sir.
Deformation impact
on Deck 15,
Science section.
Damage?
WORF: Reports coming in.
Minimal damage.
Mr. La Forge,
I'm still having difficulty
controlling the shuttlecraft.
LA FORGE: Aye, sir.
Your krellide storage cells
are losing their charge.
Maintaining manual
control is going to become
increasingly difficult.
Estimated distance
to the nebula's perimeter?
DATA:
4.7 million kilometers, sir.
Is there a way to transfer
the microfusion thrusters
so I can get a power boost?
DATA:
Possibly.
If you augment
the thruster sequencing
so that the inertial
dampening fields...
Relative bearing 27...
make that 285.255.
Commander, the shuttle
is out of control.
Mr. O'Brien, do you have
the Captain's signal?
O'Brien: I'm having trouble
locking on, sir.
Sir, the shuttle's inertial
dampeners have failed.
It is breaking up.
Let's get him out of there.
Now would be a good time,
Mr. O'Brien.
Did we get him back?
O'BRIEN:
Aye, sir, we got him.
PICARD:
I'm a little dizzy, Number One,
but none the worse.
I'm on my way.
Acknowledged, sir.
Commander, we are
nearing the perimeter.
One million kilometers away.
All right,
let's make a run for it.
McKNIGHT:
Aye, sir.
We're clear of
the nebula, sir.
Ensign, plot a course
for Starbase 260. Warp two.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Hi.
The place looks great.
Thank you.
It is much less spartan,
is it not?
Much less.
It looks great.
It really does.
It looks... great.
Jenna, you are
repeating yourself.
I have often found this
to be indicative
of a mental distraction.
Is that a correct assumption
in this instance?
Um, I'm afraid it is.
Then perhaps we should
begin our meal.
Among humans, a low serum
glucose level is...
Data, I think
we should talk.
Could you sit down?
Um...
I'm not sure how to begin.
What is the subject?
You and I.
Our relationship.
Yes?
Data, sometimes
people blindly make
the same mistake
again and again.
Are you currently experiencing
this phenomenon?
I didn't see it until today.
I got out of a relationship
with an unemotional man
and I got right back
into another one...
with...
with a man who's absolutely
incapable of emotion.
Hmm... there does appear
to be a recurring motif.
You were so kind
and attentive.
I thought that
would be enough.
Is it not?
No, it's not.
Because as close
as we are, I...
I don't really matter to you.
Not really.
Nothing I can say or do
will ever make you happy
or sad...
or touch you in any way.
That is a valid projection.
It is apparent that my reach
has exceeded my grasp
in this particular area.
I am, perhaps,
not nearly so human
as I aspire to become.
If you are ready to eat,
I will bring our meal.
Uh... no.
That's all right, Data.
I'm going to go now.
As you wish.
Jenna...
are we no longer...
a couple?
No, we're not.
Then I will delete
the appropriate program.
I'll see you later.
Hello, Spot.