PICARD:
Captain's Log:
Stardate 44995.3.
We are en route
to the Klingon home world
where I will participate
in the installation ceremony
of Gowron, the next designated
leader of the high council.
This visit should also provide
an opportunity
for one of my officers
to correct a grave injustice.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Am I intruding?
No, sir.
My apologies, Captain.
I can be back in uniform...
No. That won't be
necessary, Mr. Worf.
I'm not here
as your captain.
I'm here as the man
who stood with you
before the high council,
your Cha'dich.
We will arrive at your home
world in less than a day.
It is not time yet.
That doesn't sound
like the man who came
to me a year ago,
fiercely determined
to return home
to clear his father's
name or die trying.
Isn't it time to
confront the council,
to regain your family name,
let the truth be known?
I have been told that
patience is sometimes
a more effective weapon
then the sword.
Patience
is a human virtue--
one that I am glad to see
you've taken to heart--
but doesn't this
situation require
a more Klingon response?
Your discommendation
is a facade to protect
less honorable men.
It is a lie.
Lies must be challenged.
I have grown weary of
bearing this dishonor.
RIKER:
Riker to Picard.
Go ahead, Number One.
We've been intercepted
by the Klingon vessel Bortas.
They claim to be our escort.
No escort was scheduled.
The Bortas
is standing by, sir.
On screen.
Gowron, this is
an unexpected pleasure.
I must speak
with you, Picard.
We will have to
move quickly if we
are to be successful.
Successful?
Yes.
In preventing
a Klingon civil war.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
The family of Duras
is massing support.
They have many allies
on the council.
Duras died in disgrace.
By Klingon tradition,
his family should
share that disgrace.
Their corruption has
poisoned the empire.
Honor will soon
have no meaning.
And who speaks for
his family now?
Lursa and B'etor,
the sisters of Duras.
And they would claim
the leadership of
the council?
Women may not serve
on the council.
Then how...?
I don't know, but they
are plotting something.
They have
secured the loyalty
of at least three
fleet commanders.
Lursa and B'etor
are feared,
and fear is power.
I do not see what
I can do to assist.
You were first chosen
as arbiter of succession
because no Klingon
could be trusted.
You accepted this duty
and you must see it
through to the end.
You must insure
my installation.
That is
beyond my purview.
You will not support me?
I will not step outside
the traditional role
of the arbiter.
And if they attempt to
block my installation?
Then I can only assure
you that I will deal
with any challenge
according to Klingon law.
I fear that will
not be enough.
Mr. Worf, would you
escort our guest to
the transporter room?
Begin monitoring
Romulan activity
along the neutral zone,
Mr. Data,
and have the outpost
stations send us
their tactical reports.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
The Duras family
are preparing to
move against Gowron.
Backed by Romulans?
I don't know.
But there is
too much history
between the Duras
and the Romulans
to discount
the possibility.
Dismissed.
I would speak with you.
I do not hear the words
of traitors.
I am not a traitor.
You admitted your guilt
before the council.
I accepted discommendation
to protect the empire.
Protect it?
How?
It was Duras's father
who betrayed our people
to the Romulans at
Khitomer, not mine.
Duras?
There is proof of this?
There is.
Why would you accept
dishonor to protect Duras?
His family
was too powerful.
To expose him would
have split the empire.
Instead, the council
chose to blame my father.
The council knew?
I believe you to be
a man of honor, Gowron.
I ask you.
Restore my family name.
Worf...
you killed Duras.
I consider that
no small favor,
but what you ask
is impossible.
But after
your installation...
The grasp of Duras
reaches out from the grave.
Much of the council is
still loyal to his family.
I must have the council's
support to survive.
I cannot expose
their treachery.
You chose to accept
this disgrace
for the good
of the empire.
Now you must live
with your decision
like a Klingon.
( phaser firing )
( door opening )
Guinan?
It was a little quiet
down in Ten Forward
so I thought I'd get off
a little target practice.
Do you mind
if I join you?
You... practice?
I like to
keep my eye sharp.
I practice at level 14.
Hmm. I guess I could
come down to that
level for a while.
Begin program.
You know, I had a bet
with the captain that
I could make you laugh
before you became
lieutenant commander.
Not a good bet today.
I've seen you laugh.
I like it.
Klingons do not laugh.
Oh, yes, they do.
Absolutely they do.
You don't, but I've heard
Klingon belly laughs
that will curl your hair.
Your son laughs;
he's Klingon.
He is a child
and part human.
That's right,
and you're not.
You're a full Klingon,
except you don't laugh.
I do not laugh because
I do not feel like laughing.
Other Klingons
feel like laughing.
What does that say
about you?
Perhaps it says
that I do not feel
like other Klingons.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
Good game.
Don't feel bad.
I was doing this long
before you were born.
So how is he?
Your son.
He is having difficulty
adjusting to life on Earth.
Oh. I could see
where it might be hard
for the little guy,
living with humans,
being Klingon.
It could be
very confusing.
It will not be
easy for him.
No, it won't, but at
some point, he's going
to want to know
what it's like to
really be a Klingon,
just as you're
learning now.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain, I request
a leave of absence.
Mr. Worf,
request granted.
Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant.
Qapla!
And good luck.
Lieutenant Worf, personal Log:
Stardate 44996.1.
I have located
the Klingon ship
on which my brother, Kurn,
serves as captain
and have arranged
to meet him.
It has been too long,
my brother.
Too long.
We have much
to discuss.
I have asked Gowron to
restore our family honor.
He has refused.
Gowron will not live
to see the day he
leads the council.
What do you mean?
He stands alone,
surrounded by his enemies.
Lursa and B'etor
would have him killed,
and if they don't,
I will.
You will?
Gowron is weak.
The family of Duras
must never be allowed
to rule the council.
Our leaders
have failed us.
They no longer deserve
our loyalty.
It is time to sweep away
the old council
and put a new one
in its place.
How can this be done?
I already have the support
of four squadron commanders
in key strategic sectors.
When the time comes,
they will follow me.
Join us, Worf,
and we will usher in
a new era and regain
our family name.
No.
What?!
Gowron has completed
the rite of succession.
It is our duty
to support him.
Gowron spits in your
face when you ask him
to give back what
is rightfully ours
and you would
support him.
We cannot regain honor
by acting dishonorably.
I will not support Gowron.
I am the elder brother,
Kurn.
I speak for our family.
We will back Gowron.
But not now.
Not yet.
We will wait
until he feels the
grasp of his enemies
around his throat.
Then we will offer
him our support
and the price will
be the restoration
of our family name.
It will be difficult
to convince my allies
to back Gowron,
but I will try.
I must go
to the Mempa sector
to meet with the other
squadron commanders.
Contact me when you have
gained their support.
Then I will be
ready for Gowron.
PICARD:
Captain's Log:
Stardate 44996.8.
My role as arbiter of
succession has again brought me
to the great hall of
the Klingon high council.
Nadev ghos.
Have you reached
a decision
regarding the
succession of power?
Qaja plu d'itch jung!
La woq yon ghir
klas qimha!
Gowron.
Doj hon.
Gowron, son of M'rel,
hakt'em.
The arbiter confirms
that you have completed
the rite of succession.
Your enemies
have been destroyed.
You stand alone.
Do you wish to
claim leadership
of the council?
I wish it.
Are there no
other challengers?
There is one.
I will challenge him.
An arrogant child?
Who are you?
I am Toral,
son of Duras.
Duras had no son.
But he did, Gowron.
So this is
your doing, Lursa.
We wish to
address the council.
Lursa, B'etor,
come forward.
Members of
the high council,
it is a day of rejoicing
for the family of Duras
and the Klingon empire.
We have discovered that
our brother did indeed
have a son and heir.
This is outrageous.
Duras had no mate.
Where did you
find him, Lursa?
In a harlot's bed chamber?
I will personally cut
your tongue out, yintagh!
Impudent wretch.
A simple genetic scan
will prove his bloodline
is valid.
The illegitimate son
of Duras cannot rule
the high council.
The arbiter will
consider his validity.
Len'mat.
Our allies on the council
backed Toral's claim.
It's in Picard's
hands now.
Excellent.
Everything is proceeding
as scheduled.
Why not just kill Picard?
Fool! Do we want the
Federation as our enemy?
No.
At least not yet.
But when
the time is right,
we will deal
with the Federation
and Captain Picard.
I have met with the other
squadron commanders here.
Three will join us,
one will not.
That gives us enough
strength to control
seven key sectors.
Do you know the strength
of our enemies?
They have at least
seven squadrons,
but most of the fleet
has not decided
which banner to follow.
Well, Gowron is nearly
out of options.
Soon he will have
no choice.
I will return soon
to the home world.
We shall meet then.
Do you also require
the original logs
recorded during
the attack, Lieutenant?
Everything we have
on the Khitomer massacre.
We can provide you
with our analysis of
the communications
between the Khitomer
outpost and the
Romulan ships.
However, for a complete
record, you will have to
contact Starbase 24.
Mr. Worf, have you
cancelled your leave?
No, sir.
Lieutenant, would you
join me in my ready room?
Mr. Worf, you are
using our files on
the Khitomer massacre
as evidence against
Duras's father.
Yes, sir.
Do you not see an inherent
conflict of interest here?
Sir, those Federation
records will help me prove
my father was falsely
accused of treason.
You are using your position
as a starfleet officer
to affect political change
on your planet.
There could not be a
worse compromise of our
fundamental principles.
Do not tie my hands now.
I must be able to prove
my father's innocence.
Those Federation records
can do that.
Mr. Worf...
here I am, lecturing you
on a conflict of interest
while I'm desperately trying
to avoid one of my own.
Do you think I wish to
allow the Duras family
to solidify their hold
on the council?
Do you think I cannot
see for myself
the implications
for the Federation?
Good Lord, Duras tried
to have me killed.
All of my instincts,
my training,
my very being
as a starfleet officer
are at odds
with my responsibility
as arbiter of the
Klingon high council.
We walk the same
tightrope between
two worlds, you and I.
We must try our very best
to keep those
two worlds separate
or we shall
certainly fall.
Yes, sir.
I will make the
Khitomer massacre files
available to anyone
who wants them--
to the high council,
to the Duras family,
to you... anyone.
Thank you, sir.
Mr. Worf...
this is as far
as I will go.
RIKER:
Riker to Picard.
Yes, Number One?
There's a message coming in
for you from the surface.
It's coded personal.
Send it through.
Captain.
Welcome.
Please, come in.
Be seated.
Something to drink,
Captain?
Tea.
Earl Grey, perhaps?
Thank you.
You come alone
and unarmed.
Nothing will be served
by killing the arbiter
before his decision.
Nevertheless,
a brave act, Captain.
B'etor.
Your invitation
was unexpected.
We should have
extended it much sooner.
We don't want you
to judge us
by your experience
with our brother.
B'ETOR:
Duras was a fool.
He deserved to die.
Forget him.
We have.
We do not wish
to be your enemy.
Quite the opposite.
That pleases me.
Have you...
have you made
your decision
regarding
Toral's challenge?
I'm pursuing it
with due vigilance.
Allow me to heat up
your tea.
Toral has the bloodline
to lead the empire
into the next century.
He has the support
of the people.
Then it remains to see if
he has the support of law.
But he must.
Surely you can see that.
I'll tell you what I see.
If I find
Toral's challenge valid,
the two of you will
very quickly gain
control of the council
and Gowron
will be found dead
shortly thereafter.
If I reject Toral's claim,
you will accuse me of
serving Federation interest
and it will serve
as a rallying cry
to declare war
and overthrow Gowron.
You see very clearly,
Captain, but one
thing is missing.
If you rule against us
and we are victorious
in a war against Gowron...
Which we would be.
...it will mean the
end of the alliance
with the Federation.
And we would hate to
see that happen as
much as you would.
This is not a threat,
Captain.
Just an unfortunate
truth.
So why be our enemy when
you can be our friend?
You have manipulated
the circumstances
with the skill
of a Romulan.
My decision
will be announced
at high sun tomorrow.
Excellent tea.
Good day, ladies.
What is your decision?
K'tal, this council knows
the law of heredity well.
G'now juk hol pajhard.
A son shall share
in the honors or
crimes of his father.
Toral is Duras's son.
That has been established
by genetic scan,
but with due respect to
the traditions and laws
of this high council,
there is no basis
for accepting a petition
for leadership
from a boy who
has fought no battles,
shed no blood
for his people,
nor earned
honor for himself.
One day, perhaps,
he shall, but not now.
Duras is dead.
His claim to the
leadership died with him.
Gowron shall lead
the council.
The arbiter has ruled.
There are
no more challenges.
Does the Federation
dictate Klingon destiny
or do we?
Follow me, and I will
show you honor.
Follow him, and you reject
all Klingon law.
Can you not see
what you are doing?
Are you blind to
what they represent?
Then go.
Your blood will paint
the way to the future.
Your message said
it was urgent.
What do you want?
Your forces
are weak, Gowron.
You need help to fight
the family of Duras.
From one
dishonored Klingon.
I offer you four
Klingon squadrons.
Why would they follow you,
a starfleet officer?
They are pledged to
support my brother, Kurn.
Kurn is your brother?
Yes. His true bloodlines
were hidden to protect him.
Kurn will follow me?
He has opposed me
in the past.
I am the elder brother.
He will do as I say.
What is it
you want in return?
You know my price.
The return
of your honor
for the support
of four squadrons.
No. That will
not be enough.
The Duras family controls
most of the fleet.
We must have
Federation help.
They will not intervene.
Perhaps not yet,
but starfleet command
will listen to Picard
and Picard...
listens to you.
I can ask nothing more
of him in this matter.
What?
My duty as
a starfleet officer...
You come to me and
demand the restoration
of your family honor
and now you hide
behind human excuses.
What are you, Worf?
Do you tremble
and quake with fear
at the approach of combat,
hoping to talk your way
out of a fight like a human
or do you hear
the cry of the warrior
calling you to battle,
calling you to glory
like a Klingon?
( explosive hit )
( speaking Klingon )
Status!
Aft shields down.
Warp coils damaged.
Red alert.
A second ship is joining
the attack on the Bortas.
It's begun.
Send an emergency signal
to any loyal ships!
Impulse engines
not responding!
Engage emergency override.
Override engaged.
Disruptors still
not responding.
The Bortas has lost
her port shields, sir.
It is unlikely they
will withstand another
hit in that quarter.
Their primary life support
has failed, sir.
The Bortas has put out
a general distress call.
Ensign Reel, plot a course
to take us safely from
the combat area.
Half impulse.
Captain, the Bortas
is Gowron's ship.
If he's the legitimate
leader of the empire,
shouldn't we help him?
If we go to the aid
of the Bortas,
we'll be dragging
the Federation into
a Klingon civil war.
What about Worf?
Ensign.
Engage.
Port shields
are still down.
Disruptors online.
Lock on target.
No. Don't you see?
Their sensors will
detect the weapons lock.
If they think we're
helpless, they will
try to board the ship.
I can aim and fire
disruptors manually when
they drop their shields.
Ghos!
35,000 kellicams.
20,000 kellicams.
Now within
transporter range.
Suh!
They're dropping
their shields!
Bah!
WORF:
Firing on second target.
They were able to raise
the shields in time.
Minor damage only.
Disruptors off-line.
All power to shields!
Shields failing.
Incoming message.
On viewer!
This is Captain Kurn
of the Hegh'ta.
We come to defend the
empire and to follow
the banner of Gowron.
You have done well,
Captain Kurn.
Lursa and B'etor
have moved more quickly
than I anticipated.
We shall not
underestimate them again.
Meet us at the great hall.
Advise the Enterprise
that their delegation
is welcome to attend
my installation as leader.
PICARD:
Captain's Log:
Stardate 44998.3.
With new-found support,
Gowron has chosen to proceed
with the installation ceremony.
The Enterprise has returned
so that I may perform my final
duty as arbiter of succession.
Receive now the loyalty
of the council
and of the empire.
BOTH:
Qapla!
Nadev ghos.
You both fought
as warriors.
You have proven your
hearts are Klingon!
I return
your family honor.
I give you back that
which was wrongfully
taken from you.
Let your name be
spoken once again.
You are Worf,
son of Mogh.
The Duras family is
gathering a large force
near Beta Thoridor.
As per the terms
of the treaty of alliance,
I now formally request
your assistance
in fighting these enemies
of the empire.
These enemies are Klingon.
By right and tradition,
I am the sole leader.
All who oppose me
are traitors.
I understand your position,
but I'm sure you're aware
that the Federation
cannot interfere
in, what is by definition,
an internal Klingon affair.
You arbitrated the
right of succession.
You are already involved.
My duties in that
regard are finished.
Captain,
we must intervene.
The Duras family is corrupt
and hungry for power
with no sense
of honor or loyalty.
They represent
a grave threat
to the security
of the Federation.
Captain...
you and I know that
they have conspired
with Romulans
in the past.
If they should be
victors in this war,
they would surely form a new
Klingon/Romulan alliance,
and that would represent
a fundamental shift of
power in this quadrant.
Starfleet
must support Gowron.
It is in the interest
of both the Federation
and the empire.
I beg you.
Support us in our cause.
Mr. Worf, I don't
have to lecture you
on the principal
of non-interference.
And as starfleet officers,
we have all sworn an oath
to uphold that
principal, whatever
our personal feelings,
and I'm sorry, I must
refuse your request.
Mr. Worf,
I'm afraid I must
recall you to duty.
The Enterprise will
be leaving this
sector immediately.
Captain, I respectfully
request that I be allowed
to take an extended
leave of absence.
Mr. Worf, your
responsibilities
as a starfleet officer
are incompatible with
remaining on board
a Klingon ship
during a time of war.
Captain...
I order you to return
to duty at once.
Then I resign my commission
as a starfleet officer.
I will await you
aboard the Bortas.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Am I intruding?
No, sir.
I understand you will be
serving onboard the Bortas.
As weapons officer.
Your tactical knowledge
and experience will
serve them well.
Thank you, sir.
Mr. Worf, are you
certain that this is
the right decision?
I was rescued from
Khitomer by humans,
raised and loved
by human parents.
I have spent most of
my life around humans,
fought beside them.
But I was born a Klingon.
My heart is of that world.
I do hear the cry
of the warrior.
I belong with my people.
Being the only Klingon
ever to serve in starfleet
gave you a singular
distinction, but...
I felt that what was unique
about you was your humanity,
compassion, generosity,
fairness.
You took the best
qualities of humanity
and made them part of you.
The result was a man
who I was proud to call
one of my officers.
I'll have your belongings
transported to the Bortas.
Thank you, sir.
Attention on deck.
Permission to leave
the ship, sir.
Permission granted.
Qapla.
Good-bye.
Dismissed.
Picard has rejected
Gowron's plea for help.
The Enterprise
has left orbit.
Coward! He didn't have
the courage to face us.
The Federation...
WOMAN:
Celebrate later, Toral.
We should not discount
Jean-Luc Picard yet.
He is human,
and humans have a way
of showing up when
you least expect them.