Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation.
We will have to move quickly
if we are to be successful.
Successful?
Yes. In preventing
a Klingon Civil War.
I would speak with you.
I do not hear
the words of traitors.
It was Duras' father
who betrayed our people
to the Romulans at Khitomer,
not mine.
We have discovered
that our brother did indeed
have a son and heir.
Follow me and I will
show you honor.
Your blood will paint
the way to the future.
If we go to the aid of
the Bortas,
we'll be dragging the Federation
into a Klingon Civil War.
GOWRON: You both
fought as warriors.
I return your family honor.
Mr. Worf, your responsibilities
as a Starfleet officer
are incompatible
with remaining onboard
a Klingon ship during
a time of war.
Then I resign my commission
as a Starfleet officer.
Picard has rejected
Gowron's plea for help.
( chuckles )
The Enterprise
has left orbit.
We should not discount
Jean-Luc Picard yet.
He is human...
and humans have a way
of showing up
when you least expect them.
And now the conclusion.
KURN: Maintain course.
Status of warp engines.
Warp engines at 60%.
KURN:
Status of shields.
Aft shields
buckling.
Transfer auxiliary power
to shields.
Aft shields are gone.
We cannot win.
We must withdraw.
Keep your place.
New course... 307,
mark 275.
But, sir, that takes us
dangerously close to the--
GhoS!
WORF: We are entering
the star's corona.
We will reach the photosphere
in 30 seconds.
Standby to enter
warp on my command.
Set course 250, mark 015.
Shields failing.
Outer hull temperature
exceeding design limit.
Captain!
Maintain course.
They're
closing on us.
Standby.
Dah!
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45020.4.
We have arrived at Starbase 234
where I've taken
the opportunity
to make a proposal
to Fleet Admiral Shanthi.
There have been
three major engagements
in the past two weeks,
all of them won
by ships loyal to
the Duras family.
None of which is
our concern, Jean-Luc.
The Klingon Civil War is,
by definition,
an internal matter
of the empire.
Agreed. But if the Duras are
being aided by the Romulans,
it becomes very much
our concern.
The Romulans have been
attempting to destroy
the Klingon Federation
Alliance for the past 20 years.
And at the same time, the Duras
have been secretly conspiring
with the Romulans.
Doesn't it strike you as odd
that the Duras
are able to field
such an overpowering
force against Gowron,
that they outmatch him
at almost every turn?
Some would call it
good leadership.
And some would say that
they must be getting help.
The Romulans are prepared
to take enormous risks
to gain any advantage
over the Federation.
Can we seriously believe
that now, with the future
of the Klingon Empire
in the balance,
they are content
to standby and watch?
What is it you propose, Captain?
We must stop the flow
of supplies and equipment
to the Duras from
the Romulans.
What I propose
is that we send a fleet
to the Romulan/Klingon border.
We take no offensive action,
but we will be in a position
to expose any Romulan supplies
that attempt to cross
the border.
A blockade?
Exactly.
But how will you overcome
the Romulan
cloaking device?
My chief engineer
has developed a system
that should nullify
that advantage.
Each ship will send out
an active tachyon beam
to the other
blockading ships.
Now, in theory,
any cloaked vessel
that attempts to pass
between our ships
must cross that beam
and be detected.
I'll have to clear this
with the Federation Council.
In the meantime,
assemble your fleet, Captain.
Nicely done.
I hope we know
what we're doing.
So do I, Number One.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45021.3.
Convincing Starfleet Command
to establish a blockade
was relatively painless.
Implementing that plan
is proving more troublesome.
RIKER:
Starfleet is stretched
pretty thin across
this quadrant.
There are only
about 12 ships
within a day's travel
at this position.
The only others ships available
are either in Spacedock
for repairs
or still
under construction.
Most of 'em don't even
have full crews yet.
We could probably scare up
seven, maybe eight more ships.
Mr. La Forge, can you implement
your tachyon detection grid
with 20 ships?
LA FORGE: It's possible.
But the more ships,
the bigger the net
we can throw.
All right, I want to add
the Tian An Men,
the Sutherland,
and the Hermes,
whether the yard superintendent
says they're ready or not.
Mr. Data, will you
select a group
of experienced
Enterprise officers
to augment the crews
of those ships?
Aye, sir.
Will, I want you
to command the Excaliber.
Her crew was reassigned when
she put in for repairs.
Geordi, you will be
his first officer.
Aye, sir.
I want the fleet underway
by 0900 tomorrow.
Thank you,
gentlemen.
Yes, Mr. Data?
May I ask a question, sir,
of a personal nature?
Yes.
I am confused.
Why have I not been
assigned to command
a ship in the fleet, sir?
Well, I felt that you would be
needed here.
Why do you ask?
You have commented on the lack
of senior officers
available for this mission.
I believe my 26 years of
Starfleet service
qualifies me for such a post.
However, if you
do not feel
the time has arrived for an
android to command a starship,
perhaps I should address
myself to improving--
Commander...
I believe
the starship Sutherland
will need a captain.
I think of no one better suited
for that task than you.
Thank you, sir.
( yelling and growling )
( low growling )
( loud roar )
( growling and yelling )
( laughing )
You always did have fools
working for you, Larg.
Now, you don't
have as many.
You were lucky, Kurn,
but luck always runs out.
Someday, I will stand
over your broken corpse
and drink to the victory
of the Duras.
( laughing )
Ah, Worf...
Worf, good.
This piece of baktag
is Captain Larg.
He commanded the squadron
that tried to
destroy us yesterday.
Ah, the infamous Worf,
son of Mogh.
What is that
you are wearing?
That is the uniform
of a Klingon!
( laughs )
The capital city
is neutral ground,
and Larg's men are
all around us,
as are mine.
Good to drink
with you, Kurn.
May you die well.
Die well, Larg.
( growling )
( laughing )
You drink with
our enemies?
How many are
Gowron's men?
How many are Duras?
Does it matter?
When we meet in battle,
we will fight to the death.
But here,
here we're all warriors,
all Klingons.
The repairs to the Hegh'ta
are proceeding.
The port stabilizers--
Is there nothing in
your heart but duty?
It is my responsibility.
We all have
responsibilities and duties,
but you and I are warriors
fighting in a great war.
Think of it.
You and I will fight battles
that others can only dream of.
The time for
glory is here.
It is not a time to worry
about stabilizers.
It is a time to celebrate,
for tomorrow,
we all may die!
( roaring cheers )
Come, let us,
the sons of Mogh,
live this night as if
it were our last.
Huh? Huh? Huh?
( roaring cheer )
Worf is not
like his brother.
No.
He tries to be,
but he's still
unsure of himself.
Perhaps he needs something to
help restore his confidence.
I think he'll find
our offer appealing.
I'll make sure he does.
You've got to keep
this mixture above 90%
or we'll never leave orbit.
Thank you, Mr. Craig.
I am Lieutenant
Commander Data.
Lieutenant Commander
Christopher Hobson.
By order of Starfleet, I hereby
take command of this vessel.
Please note the time
and date in the ship's log.
Excuse me, sir.
I'd like to request
a transfer.
May I ask why?
I don't believe I'd be a
good first officer for you.
Your service record to date
suggests you would perform
that function adequately.
No, no, no.
That's not what I mean.
I don't think I'd be a
good first officer for you.
Why?
Frankly, sir, I don't
believe in your ability
to command this ship.
You're a fellow officer
and I respect that,
but no one would suggest
that a Klingon would be
a good ship's counselor,
or that a Berellian
could be an engineer.
They're just not suited
for those positions.
By the same token,
I don't think an android
is a good choice
to be captain.
I understand your concerns.
Request denied.
The Endeavor has cleared
the dock, Captain.
All ships standing by.
Good.
Course 118, mark 357,
full impulse power.
Signal the fleet
to get underway.
We'll enter warp
once we're clear of the system.
Aye, sir.
Engage.
The Romulan convoy is late.
We need those supplies.
Gowron has suffered another
loss near the Mempa system.
His forces will not
threaten you in that region
for some time.
But if Gowron--
The convoy will arrive
in due course.
A Federation fleet
has left Starbase 234.
They've set course for
Klingon territory.
How many?
At least 20 starships.
Who is commanding
this fleet?
Picard.
What does it mean?
Is the Federation
going to enter the war?
Should we attack them
before they get here?
Silence the child
or send him away.
Movar.
I want you to return to
Romulus immediately.
Have all available
ships rendezvous
at these coordinates
in two days.
Yes, Commander.
20 starships aren't
enough to wage war.
Starfleet
must be bluffing.
Perhaps.
Our forces in the Mempa sector
are now in full retreat.
They will need to regroup
near Beta Lankal.
We destroyed their supply bases
in that sector three weeks ago.
How can they
continue to fight?
They must be getting help.
KULGE: Maybe they have
better leaders.
I say you have failed
as our leader, Gowron.
There is no time for this.
We must make plans
before those forces
reach Beta Lankal.
How can we
oppose the Duras
when we continue to fight
amongst ourselves?
Gowron must answer this
challenge to his authority.
Stop it!
Do we fall upon ourselves
like a pack of Ferengi?!
The enemy is the Duras!
We are at war.
( chuckles )
Now, the war can continue.
We're crossing into
Klingon territory, Captain.
Signal the fleet to
maintain yellow alert
until further notice.
Aye, sir.
Begin long-range scans
of the Romulan border.
No uncloaked ships
within sensor range.
A few subspace anomalies,
but nothing firm.
Those anomalies
could be cloaked ships.
Could be, sir.
Open a channel to the Excalibur.
RIKER:
Excalibur, Riker here.
Deploy the fleet, Will.
It's time to spread
our net.
RIKER: Yes, sir.
We've arrived at the designated
coordinates, Captain.
All stop. Notify the flagship
that we have assumed station.
( alarm beeps )
Starboard power coupling
is overloaded.
We've got a radiation leak
on decks 10 through 12.
Why are the back-ups
not functioning?
There wasn't enough time
to test all the back-ups
before we left the yard.
Terry, I want you
down in Engineering
working on a
new coupling.
You have taken the phaser and
torpedo control units off-line.
Keith, you and I will
start bringing--
Mr. Hobson, it is inappropriate
for you to determine a course
of action without consulting
your commanding officer.
I was trying to safeguard the
lives of people on those decks.
But you're right.
Belay those orders,
everyone.
Phasers and torpedoes
are back on-line.
What should we do, sir?
You will take the phaser and
torpedo units off-line
and begin repairs of
the starboard power coupling.
Thank you, sir.
You heard the captain,
everyone.
We're ready, sir.
Mr. La Forge, how long
do you think it will take
the Romulans to detect
the tachyon field
once it's
activated?
Not long-- Romulan sensors
are as good as ours.
Very well.
Energize the network.
Commander, there's an increase
in tachyon emissions
from the Federation fleet.
SELA: They're using the beams
as a detection field.
If we try to cross it,
they'll see us,
even if we're cloaked.
Issue orders to begin work on
a way to penetrate this field.
In the meantime,
we'll have to convince
Captain Picard
he should leave.
Captain, I'm picking up
something directly ahead.
Romulan ship decloaking.
O'BRIEN:
Shall I raise shields?
Not yet.
They're hailing us, sir.
On screen.
Tasha.
No, Captain.
My name is Commander Sela.
The woman you knew as Tasha Yar
was my mother.
SELA: Deploying an invasion
fleet along our border
is a clear act
of aggression, Captain.
It will not be tolerated.
You have 20 hours
to recall your ships
and return peacefully to
Federation territory.
So, you believe her,
Counselor?
I'm not saying we should accept
her claim at face value,
but I sensed
no deception from her.
She really believes she's
the daughter of Tasha Yar.
Regardless of what she believes,
Sela can't be her daughter.
I've reviewed all of
Tasha's medical records,
and there is no indication that
she was ever pregnant.
Besides, Tasha was a child
when this woman was born.
Sela could have
been cloned.
Or had her appearance
surgically altered.
But why? What possible advantage
could there be to the Romulans?
As this now stands,
I don't think this will
have any impact
on our present strategy.
We'll continue the blockade.
Leave the next move to them.
Thank you.
( door opens and closes )
( door opens )
GUINAN:
Am I intruding?
No, not at all.
Is something wrong?
News travels fast.
I heard that
Tasha Yar's daughter
is aboard the Romulan ship.
I think that the Romulans
are just hoping
to create a distraction.
They want to keep us
off balance.
Hmm.
How much do you know
about what happened
to the last ship
called Enterprise?
The Enterprise-C?
It was lost at the
Battle of Narendra III
defending a Klingon outpost
from the Romulans.
And the survivors?
There were stories of prisoners
taken back to Romulus,
but these were only rumors.
No.
There were survivors.
And Tasha Yar
was one of them.
Guinan, that was 23 years ago.
Tasha Yar was
only a child.
I know that.
But I also know
she was aboard that ship
and she was not a child.
And I think...
you sent her there.
How can that be?
I don't know.
I just know that you did.
Tasha died...
a year before you came
on the Enterprise.
You never met her.
I know that.
If you have only
a vague intuition--
You can't just dismiss this.
If I'm right,
then you are responsible
for this whole situation.
I think it's time
that I met Commander Sela.
We are at war.
Gowron should forbid
any challenges
until we are victorious.
A Klingon does not postpone
a matter of honor.
A Klingon should place
the good of the empire
above his own pride.
Oh, so now, Gowron
no longer suits you?
Perhaps you wish
to challenge him
for the leadership
of the Council.
No!
Then do not speak
of this again.
I did not wish
to follow Gowron.
You came to me
and insisted
that we support Gowron
against the Duras family.
The time for debate is over.
We are Klingons.
He is our leader.
If that is not
enough for you,
then perhaps you made
the wrong choice
when you put
on that uniform.
( grunting )
( groaning )
Well, Captain,
what is this urgent matter
we need to discuss?
Please, won't you sit down?
I'm afraid that
you have misinterpreted
our presence here.
I want to reassure you that
we have no hostile intention.
Ah!
So, then I can tell my superiors
that a fleet
of 23 Federation starships
is on our border for what?
Humanitarian reasons?
It is our intent
to prevent any external power
from interfering
in Klingon affairs.
Nor do we have any plan to
do so.
But, Captain,
if for any reason
we chose to enter
Klingon territory,
how would you stop us?
With our cloaking devices,
we can slip by you at will.
Then why don't you
just take your ships across?
You sound eager for us to try.
Perhaps you've discovered
a method in detecting our ships?
However, I don't think
you asked me here
to discuss
our military situation.
All right.
Why did I invite you here?
You want the answer to the
only question on your mind--
how could Tasha Yar
be my mother?
It's been suggested
that she was on board
the Enterprise-C
when it was destroyed
24 years ago,
that she was one
of the survivors
and that obviously,
you are a product
of a union between
her and a Romulan.
( chuckles )
But you know that's impossible.
She would have been a child
when that battle occurred.
But you claim that
it is possible--
that you're the daughter
of Tasha Yar.
Yes, she was on that ship
24 years ago.
She was sent there
by you from the future.
She was among those
few who survived.
They were all to
have been executed
after the interrogation,
but a Romulan general
saw her and became
enamored with her.
So, a deal was struck.
Their lives
would be spared
if she became his consort.
I was born a year later.
I want to meet your mother.
Can you arrange that?
One night when I was
four years old she came to me.
She bundled me up and she
told me to stay quiet
as we left the compound.
I realized
she was taking me away.
She was taking me away from
my home, my father,
So, I cried out.
My father offered her life.
He gave her a home.
He gave her a child.
And how did she
repay him?
By betrayal.
They executed her.
Everything in me that was human
died that day with my mother.
All that's left now is Romulan.
Never doubt that.
Doubts?
I'm full of them.
( sighs )
But nothing in my experience
can persuade me
that what you have
told me is true.
And I do know one thing--
it will not affect my judgment
at our next encounter.
You have 14 hours, Captain.
I suggest
you use them wisely.
( raspy purring )
( lustful growl )
( passionate purring )
( Worf moaning )
( laughing )
Something wrong?
Welcome, Worf,
son of Mogh.
What do you want?
The same as you--
personal honor,
glory for the empire.
Your family has never
valued honor.
You only knew
our brother.
We are not like him.
Our brother
made many mistakes.
One was to make
you an enemy.
We would rather
be your friends.
Then you should not
have opposed Gowron.
Gowron is nothing.
Toral is Duras'
only son,
and he will be the
leader of the Council.
In your heart,
even you know that.
But Toral
needs guidance.
A firm hand.
A father figure.
That could be you...
if you were mated
to B'Etor.
The rewards could be greater
than you could imagine.
Nothing would
stand in our way.
We could rule the
empire together.
Join us, Worf,
and usher in a new
era for our people.
Era, where honor has
no meaning?
Where Klingons trade loyalties
in dark rooms
and the empire
is ruled from Romulus?
( single beep )
SELA: Enough, Lursa.
You've failed.
I need to know the strength
and capabilities of
the Federation fleet.
I don't have time for this.
Turn him over to the guard.
B'Etor can have him back
when they finish with him.
Come!
In 13 hours, we'll be forced to
either withdraw from the border
or fight the Romulan fleet.
Neither alternative
is acceptable.
We must expose their
involvement before the deadline.
What is it you propose?
If you launch a
full-scale attack now,
then the Duras fleet will
call for supplies.
Lursa and B'Etor
will call for help.
The Romulans will try
to run the blockade,
and we'll be ready for them.
And once the Romulan connection
has been exposed,
support will fall away
from Lursa and B'Etor.
Very well.
I will make
preparations.
One thing more,
Picard.
Worf has been captured
by the Duras.
I hope he dies well.
Qapla'!
When Gowron begins his attack,
then we will make our move.
Excalibur will fall back
with engine problems.
And you will take the
Akagi and the Hornet
to this position,
which will open
a small gap in
our detection net.
And if the Romulans are already
aware of the tachyon field,
they should run the
blockade at that point.
Exactly, but when they try
to bring their ships through,
the Enterprise
and the Tian An Men
will swing around,
close the gap...
catch them in the act.
Very nice.
I'd better get back.
Good luck, Will.
Good luck, Captain.
We've just received
an urgent message
from Lursa and B'Etor.
Gowron's forces have
attacked in three sectors.
The Duras are
nearing defeat.
You mean they were
caught unprepared
and now,
they're crying for help.
( sighs )
Have the science sections
found a way to circumvent
the detection grid yet?
We think so.
Just before
we cross the border
we'll send out a massive
tachyon pulse.
A burst that large
should cause
enough interference
to disable
the part of
their network.
Good.
MOVAR: One of their ships is
moving off the blockade line.
Their warp drive is failing.
Picard is
redeploying the fleet
to compensate for
the missing ship.
There's a gap
opening in the net.
SELA: He doesn't have enough
ships to maintain the network.
If we act quickly,
we can move through.
Commander?!
No.
I don't think so.
But it's what
we've been waiting for!
Yes, I know,
and so does Picard.
He's giving us
exactly what we need,
and he expects us to take it.
No. We won't step
into Picard's trap.
We will disable part
of his network...
here, where
they're weakest.
We'll direct
the energy burst
right at the ship with
the android captain.
Sir, the detection net
is picking up activity
from the Romulans.
15 cloaked ships
spreading out
along the border.
Signal the fleet
to stand by.
Aye, sir.
Now.
Come to course 080,
mark 295.
( alarm sounds )
There's a disruption
in the tachyon detectors.
It's localized to this
segment of the net.
Open a channel to
the Sutherland.
Data here, sir.
We're reading
a disruption
of the tachyon net
in your area.
DATA: Yes, sir.
The Romulans have released
a high-energy burst.
The net is no longer
effective in a radius
of 10 million kilometers
around the Sutherland.
That's where
they're going through.
Send a signal to the fleet.
All ships to fall back and
rendezvous at Gamma Eridon.
We'll re-establish
the net there.
Aye, sir.
All Federation ships proceed at
maximum warp to Gamma Eridon.
Acknowledge the signal.
Ensign, lay in a course
and engage at warp 9.3.
Aye, sir.
What are you doing?
In disrupting the
detection net,
the Romulans may
have caused a residual
tachyon signature to form
around their own ships.
But we have no way
of detecting it.
All stop.
Aye, sir. All stop.
Sir...
the fleet's been ordered
to Gamma Eridon.
The tachyon signatures
will not last long.
By the time the fleet is
deployed, it will be too late.
Begin to reconfigure
the sensors
to detect ionized
particle traces.
The entire area's been flooded
with tachyon particles.
We'll never be able to find
what we're looking for.
I am aware of the difficulties.
Please bring
the phasers back on-line.
That will flood three decks
with radiation.
We will initiate radiation
protocol when necessary.
You don't give a damn
about the people whose lives
you're throwing away,
we're not just machines--
Mr. Hobson!
You will carry out my orders
or I will relieve you of duty.
Yes, sir.
Captain, the Sutherland
isn't heading
for the rendezvous point.
She's come to
a full stop.
Open a channel.
The Enterprise wants to know
the reason we've stopped.
Display sensor schematic.
Display sensor sweep,
maximum range.
Are you going to answer
the Enterprise?
Overlay display
with tachyon emissions.
Highlight any tachyon
signatures
which show subspace
inertial displacement.
Concentrate a sensor sweep
in that area.
HOBSON:
Sir, this is pointless.
Those readings
could be anything.
There's no way for us
to be sure
the Romulans
are out there.
Reconfigure photon
torpedo warhead yields.
Set for high energy burst,
level six.
Level six?
But that won't even--
Do it!
Torpedoes ready.
Another message coming in.
It's Captain Picard.
PICARD: Mr. Data,
you were ordered to rendezvous
with the fleet at Gamma Eridon.
Acknowledge.
Stand by, Captain.
Mr. Hobson, prepare to fire.
Didn't you hear?
Captain Picard wants us--
Fire.
Fire!
They have
discovered us.
Reverse course.
Order the fleet back
to Romulan territory.
Commander, the Duras
need this convoy.
Without these supplies,
they cannot win.
We've been discovered.
It's over.
But what should I tell
Lursa and B'Etor?
Tell them...
they're on their own.
They're changing course,
heading back to Romulan space.
Make a full report
to the flagship.
Take the main
phasers off-line
and begin radiation cleanup
of the affected decks.
Yes, sir...
Captain.
Defeat.
How? Where are
the Romulans?
They never came.
( Worf groans )
( spits )
Kill him.
( explosion )
No!
( grunts )
Toral...
the next leader
of the empire.
Gowron is looking forward
to seeing you again.
Captain's personal Log,
Stardate 45025.4.
It is with a profound
sense of relief
that I have ordered the fleet
back to Federation territory
following
the Romulan withdrawal
and the news of Gowron's
victory.
We have arrived
at the Klingon home world
where I will present
the High Council
with a full report on our
encounter with the Romulans.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain, I wish
to submit myself
for disciplinary action.
I have disobeyed
a direct order
from a superior officer.
Although the result of
my actions proved positive,
the ends cannot justify
the means.
No, they can't.
However, the claim
"I was only following orders"
has been used to justify too
many tragedies in our history.
Starfleet doesn't want officers
who will blindly follow orders
without analyzing the situation.
Your actions were appropriate
for the circumstances,
and I have noted
that in your record.
Mr. Data?
Nicely done.
Sir.
The Council appreciates
your report, Captain.
The information
on the Romulan supply ships
will prove very useful.
Before you leave...
there is one last matter
to attend to.
Bring him.
Toral, son of Duras.
You stand convicted of treason.
The Duras family will one day
rule the empire.
Perhaps...
but not today.
Worf...
this child's family
wrongly took your name
and your honor
from you.
In return...
I give his life...
to you.
( drops knife )
What's wrong?
Kill him!
No.
But it's our way.
It's the Klingon way.
I know...
but it is not my way.
This boy has
done me no harm,
and I will not kill him for
the crimes of his family.
Then it falls to Kurn.
No!
No, you gave
me his life,
and I have spared it.
As you wish.
Request permission
to return to duty, sir.
Granted.