Captain's Log,
Stardate 45047.2.
The Enterprise is en route
to the uninhabited
El-Adrel system.
Its location
is near the territory
occupied by an enigmatic race
known as the Children of Tama.
Apparently, the Tamarians
arrived at El-Adrel IV
nearly three weeks ago.
They have been transmitting
a subspace signal
towards Federation space
ever since.
The signal is a standard
mathematical progression.
It does not carry
a specific message.
But they wanted us to know
they were there.
Apparently so, Number One.
Starfleet believes
their presence
is an attempt
at communication.
Commander.
Federation vessels
have encountered Tamarian ships
seven times
over the past 100 years.
Each meeting went
without incident.
However, formal relations
were not established
because communication
was not possible.
Why?
The Children of Tama were
called "incomprehensible"
by Captain Silvestri
of the Shiku Maru.
Other accounts
were comparable.
WORF:
A cause for concern.
For all we know they could be
threatening our border.
Everything in
the previous accounts
suggest a peaceable race.
We have to start from there.
Agreed. I appreciate
your prudence, Mr. Worf.
Starfleet believes
that the Tamarians
have extended a hand.
We must do the same.
Children of Tama.
I've heard rumors
about them for years.
Indeed, but are they truly
incomprehensible.
In my experience
communication is a matter
of patience, imagination.
I would like to believe
that these are qualities
that we have
in sufficient measure.
Rai and Jiri at Lungha.
Rai of Lowani.
Lowani under two moons.
Jiri of Ubaya.
Ubaya of crossed roads
at Lungha.
Lungha.
Her sky gray.
Rai and Jiri at Lungha.
Counselor?
I sense nothing
but good intentions
from them, captain.
Mr. Data?
The Tamarian seems
to be stating the proper names
of individuals and locations.
Yes, but what does it all mean?
DATA:
I'm at a loss, sir.
Captain.
Would you be prepared
to consider the creation
of a mutual
non-aggression pact
between our two peoples,
possibly leading
to a trade agreement
and cultural interchange.
Does this sound like
a reasonable course
of action to you?
( laughing )
Kadir beneath Mo Moteh.
The River Temarc.
In winter.
Impressions, Number One.
It appears
they're trying their best.
As are we,
for what it's worth.
Shaka.
When the walls fell...
Darmok.
Darmok?
Rai and Jiri
at Lungha.
Shaka.
When the walls fell...
Zima at Anzo.
Zima and Bakor.
Darmok at Tanagra.
Mirab.
His sails unfurled.
Darmok.
Mirab.
Temarc.
The river Temarc.
Darmok and Jalad at Tanagra.
Block their transporter
with the shields.
Extend to maximum range.
Not enough time.
Where is he?
The Tamarians have transported
Captain Picard
to the planet's surface
along with their own captain.
Riker to O'Brien.
It will not be possible
to transport, sir.
The Tamarian ship
has created a particle
scattering field
on the planet's ionosphere.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Riker to Captain Picard.
Do you read me, Captain?
Can we compensate?
No, sir.
The Tamarians are projecting
a particle sustaining beam
into the upper atmosphere.
The result is
a hyper-ionization
that virtually disrupts
all EM and subspace carriers.
Then they can't communicate
with their man, either.
They won't be able to beam
anyone through the field.
That is correct.
However, they have left
sensor frequencies clear.
Then they'll be able
to tell what's going on.
Analysis, Mr. Worf.
What the hell is going on?
A contest, perhaps,
between champions.
Our captain against theirs.
Theirs was armed.
Darmok and Jalad.
You want to fight
with me?
Is that it?
A challenge?
Darmok and Jalad.
I don't know who or what
Darmok or Jalad are
but I certainly didn't come here
to start a war.
Darmok and Jalad
at Tanagra.
Sorry, Captain.
( sighs )
Shaka.
When the walls fell.
Sensors show
that Captain Picard
and the Tamarian
are in apparent good health
approximately 20 meters
from each other.
Hail the Tamarian ship.
On screen.
You're holding our captain.
I want him released.
Darmok at Tanagra.
Your action could be interpreted
as an act of war.
Kiteo.
His eyes closed.
Chenza at court.
The court of silence.
Chenza!
Is there anyway to
get through to them?
Not without further study.
Close the channel,
Mr. Worf.
Gladly, sir.
Worf, I want you to assemble
a security team
take a shuttle
down to the planet.
Bring back the captain.
Aye, commander.
Sir, the Tamarians are fully
capable of stopping a shuttle.
I'm aware of that.
But disrupting
our transporter beam
and firing on a shuttle
are two entirely
different things.
I'm betting they're not
going to push it that far.
Shaka.
When the walls fell.
PICARD:
Shaka, indeed.
What now, Captain?
Will you attack me
in my sleep?
If I don't
freeze to death first.
Darmok of Kanza.
Jalad at the Kiteo.
Picard of the Federation.
Of the starship
Enterprise...
of the planet Earth.
Kadir beneath Mo Moteh.
Temba.
Temba?
What does that mean?
Fire?
Does Temba mean fire?
Temba.
His arms wide.
Temba is a person?
Because he's...
he's holding them apart in....
in... generosity?
In giving?
In taking?
Temba.
His arms wide.
Thank you.
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
I am sending a shuttlecraft
to find Captain Picard
gambling that the Tamarians
will sit tight
rather than risk an exchange
of phaser fire.
The positron density
is .013.
WORF:
Electron concentration 7.95.
Particle gradient 4/7.
We are 250 kilometers
from the planet's surface.
Commander,
the shuttle has reached
the E region
of the planet's ionosphere.
How long can we maintain
communication?
The scattering layer
induced by the Tamarians
is concentrated
in the upper D region.
The shuttle will reach that area
in approximately two minutes.
The Tamarian ship?
DATA:
Unchanged, sir.
They appear to be making
no attempt to stop us.
Maybe we called their bluff.
Status, Mr. Worf.
WORF:
Navigational, life-support,
propulsion normal.
Onboard systems do not appear
to be disrupted by the field
but I can barely
read you, Commander.
RIKER:
Acknowledged.
Maintain communication
as long as conditions permit.
Commander, I am reading
a power surge
in the Tamarian
plasma reactor.
Lieutenant Worf,
evasive maneuver sequence delta.
RIKER:
Maneuver sequence delta...
Commander,
the shuttle has been hit.
Damage?
The starboard nacelle
has been rendered inoperable.
That's all?
Riker to Worf.
Report.
Starboard thrusters
destroyed.
I may be able to land
but I will not be able
to take off.
RIKER:
Understood.
Return to the Enterprise,
Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
Enough to turn them back
but not enough to hurt them.
DATA:
Yes, sir.
The phaser pulse appears to have
been carefully attenuated
for just that effect.
Nice shooting.
LA FORGE:
I'm pretty sure
I can punch up
the annular confinement beam
enough to transport
the captain
through the field
but it's going to take me
at least a full day to do it.
Captain Picard
could be dead by then.
WORF:
I do not believe so.
I have confidence
in his ability as a warrior.
He will be victorious.
You're still assuming this is
some kind of challenge ritual.
We can't be
certain of that.
Agreed.
We're only making educated
guesses about their motivations
no more than that.
Then why do we wait?
If we attack
the ship now
they will not
be able to maintain
their scattering field.
Which might start a shooting
match and for all we know a war.
And we might still not be able
to save the captain.
It would end
this stalemate.
It's too much
of a risk.
I'll take that course
when it's the last one left.
Who the hell
are these people?
There's got to be some way
to get through to them.
As I have said,
with further study,
it may be possible to...
Then do it.
Deanna, help him.
I want something
by 0900 hours.
Now where have you gone to,
my friend?
Forgive the intrusion, Captain
but I need some answers.
Darmok at Tanagra.
Shaka! Mirab.
His sails unfurled.
Darmok.
Mirab.
DATA:
Freeze.
"Darmok."
( sighs )
Well, it seems to be a point
of contention between them.
Perhaps something
the Tamarian captain proposed
that the first officer
didn't like.
The apparent emotional dynamic
does seem to support
that assumption.
As with the other terms
used by the Tamarian
this appears to be
a proper noun.
The name clearly carries
a meaning for them.
Computer, search
for the term "Darmok"
in all linguistic data bases
for this sector.
COMPUTER:
Searching.
Darmok is the name
of the seventh dynasty emperor
on Kanda IV
a mythohistorical hunter
on Shantil III
a colony on Malindi VII
a frozen dessert
on Razna V, a...
Stop search.
Computer, how many entries
are there for "Darmok"?
COMPUTER:
Forty-seven.
( sighs )
All our technology
and experience
our universal translator,
our years in space
contact with more
alien cultures
than I can even remember.
I have encountered
1,754 non-human races
during my tenure
in Starfleet.
And we still can't even
say hello to these people.
Correct.
A single word can lead
to tragedy
one word misspoken
or misunderstood
and that could happen here,
Data, if we fail.
Replay at time index 144.
Darmok at Tanagra.
Freeze.
Computer, search
for the term "Tanagra."
all data bases.
COMPUTER:
Searching.
Tanagra, ruling family
on Gallos II
a ceremonial drink
on Lerishi IV
an island continent
on Shantil III.
Stop.
Shantil III.
Computer, cross-reference
the last entry
with the previous search index.
COMPUTER:
Darmok is the name
of a mythohistorical hunter
on Shantil III.
I think we've got something.
A captain's log?
( shouting )
Darmok!
Darmok and Jalad
at Tanagra.
I was curious.
I meant no harm.
Shaka! Temba.
His arms wide. Temba.
No. Enough! I'm not
going to fight you.
You will just have...
( roaring sound )
Darmok and Jalad
at Tanagra.
( roaring )
Temba!
His arms wide!
I'll go along
with that.
( roaring )
Commander,
sensors are picking up
an electromagnetic disturbance
approaching
the captain's position.
Analysis?
A variable induction field--
possibly
a life-form.
How close is it
to the captain?
The field is erratic--
appearing and disappearing--
but it appears
to be moving toward him.
Attacking?
Riker to La Forge.
La Forge here.
How close are we
on that transporter?
Two hours, maybe three.
I want the captain
out of there now!
That's not
very likely, sir.
I don't want to hear that,
Commander.
Lefler,
what's
the resonance frequency?
.34 over standard.
I want
a resolution of .53
at the very least.
Commander, I'll need about
two more minutes.
But there's a good chance
this isn't going to work.
If it fails...
I know.
We will have tipped our hand
to the Tamarians.
But that's a chance
we have to take.
Agreed.
La Forge, proceed.
We're on it.
La Forge out.
Riker to Transporter Room One.
O'Brien here,
Commander.
RIKER:
Stand by, Mr. O'Brien.
( electrical crackling )
Mirab.
His sails unfurled?
Come.
Shaka.
When the walls fell.
( electrical crackling )
( sighs )
Shaka.
When the walls fell.
Shaka...
you said that before
when I was trying
to build a fire.
Is that a failure?
An inability
to do something?
Darmok and Jalad...
At Tanagra.
I remember the words
but I don't understand.
( loud crackling )
Matrix levels?
Annular convergence
439.205.
Confinement
resolution .527.
That isn't
going to do it.
Increase thermal input
coefficient to 150%.
Increasing now.
RIKER:
Status, La Forge.
We're almost there, Commander.
Lefler,
shunt the overload
to the phase transition
sequencers in Transporter One.
Yes, sir.
La Forge to O'Brien.
Go ahead, Commander.
LA FORGE:
Confirm phase sequencer linkage.
Link confirmed.
Ready whenever you are, sir.
( roaring )
Uzani.
His army at Lashmir.
At Lashmir.
Was it like this
at Lashmir?
A similar situation
to the one
we're facing here?
( loud crackling )
( crackling stops )
Uzani...
his army with fist open.
A strategy?
With fist open?
With fist open.
His army with fists closed.
With fists
closed?
An army with fists opened...
to lure the enemy...
with fists closed...
to attack?
That's how you communicate,
isn't it--
by citing example.
By metaphor!
Uzani's army with...
with fist open.
Sokath!
His eyes uncovered!
( violent crackling roar )
( creature shrieks angrily )
( shrieks )
( groans )
No! No!
I've got a piece of him,
Commander, but that's all.
Boost the confinement beam!
157 over standard.
It's as solid as it'll go,
Commander.
( groans )
( groaning )
The Tamarian and the entity
are in close proximity.
The Tamarian's life signs
are fluctuating.
The scattering field is
still in full force.
What the hell is wrong
with them?
Their sensors can read what's
going on as well as ours can.
Riker to O'Brien. Report.
The field's
still deflecting the signal.
There just isn't
enough of him, sir.
Open a channel
to the Tamarian ship.
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
Your captain is under attack.
Drop your particle field.
Kailash...
when it rises.
They have closed
the channel.
O'Brien to Bridge.
I can't hold him, Commander.
( electronic crackling )
( gasping )
Shaka...
When the walls fell.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 45048.8.
Our attempt to transport
Captain Picard back to the ship
has failed.
My options are narrowing,
and my patience
is all but gone.
Here's the situation
on El-Adrel.
The entity has moved off
several hundred meters.
CRUSHER:
Captain Picard's bioscan
readings are stable.
The Tamarian's are not.
He may be injured.
RIKER: if the entity decides
to attack again
the captain
may be facing it alone.
Well, the transporter's
out of the question.
The Tamarians have deepened
the scattering field
to the D region
of the ionosphere.
There's no
getting through.
Unless we attack
the ship itself.
Are you able to pinpoint the
source of their particle beam?
They're using
a polarity coil generator
located after
their warp drive.
It's pretty heavily shielded.
Could we get through
with our phasers?
( sighs )
Not with the first spread.
It take a couple of hits.
RIKER:
That's not good enough.
I need to knock out their
scattering field with one shot.
Get the captain back
onto the Enterprise
before they know
what happened.
LA FORGE:
If we selectively target
the amplification pathways
around the generator
it should be just as effective.
And we could do it
in one burst.
How long will that take
to set up?
Worf and I would have to
adjust the pre-fire chamber.
That would give us
the focus we need.
A few hours?
Make it so.
I would prefer to find
a peaceful solution.
If we could talk our way
out of this one
that much the better.
Unfortunately,
it may not be that simple.
What did you find out?
The Tamarian ego structure
does not seem to allow
what we normally think
of as self-identity.
Their ability to abstract
is highly unusual.
They seem to communicate
through narrative imagery--
a reference to the individuals
and places which appear
in their mythohistorical
accounts.
It's as if I were to say to you,
"Juliet on her balcony."
An image of romance.
Exactly.
Imagery is everything
to the Tamarians.
It embodies
their emotional states
their very thought processes.
It's how they communicate
and it's how
they think.
If we know how they think
shouldn't we be able to get
something across to them?
No, sir.
The situation is
analogous to understanding
the grammar of a language
but none of the vocabulary.
If I didn't know who Juliet was,
or what she was doing on
that balcony
the image alone
wouldn't have any meaning.
TROI:
That's correct.
For instance, we know the Darmok
was a great hero, a hunter,
and that Tanagra was an island,
but that's it.
Without the details,
there's no understanding.
It is necessary for us
to learn the narrative
from which the Tamarians
draw their imagery.
Given our current relations,
that does not appear likely.
Darmok and Jalad...
at Tanagra.
Our situation
is similar to theirs.
I understand that.
But I need to know more.
You must tell me more
about Darmok and Jalad.
Tell me...
You used the words
"Temba, his arms wide"
when you gave me
the knife and the fire.
Could that mean give?
Temba?
His arms wide.
Darmok.
Give me more
about Darmok.
Darmok on the ocean.
Darmok.
The ocean.
Darmok on the ocean.
A metaphor
for being alone?
Isolated?
Darmok on the ocean.
( groans )
You all right?
Kiazi's children.
Their faces wet.
Temba. His arms open.
Give me more about
Darmok on the ocean.
Tanagra on the ocean.
Darmok at Tanagra.
At Tanagra?
A country?
Tanagra on the ocean?
An island?
Temba, his arms wide.
Jalad on the ocean.
Jalad at Tanagra.
He went to the same island
as Darmok.
Darmok and Jalad at Tanagra.
The beast at Tanagra.
The beast?
There was a creature at Tanagra?
Darmok and Jalad,
the beast of Tanagra.
They arrive separately.
They... they struggle together
against a common foe.
The beast at Tanagra.
Darmok and Jalad
at Tanagra.
on the ocean.
They left together.
Darmok and Jalad on the ocean.
The ocean...
Zinda!
His face black.
His eyes red.
( groaning )
Callimas at Bahar.
You hoped that something like
this would happen, didn't you?
You knew there was a dangerous
creature on this planet
and you knew from
the tale of Darmok
that a danger shared
might sometimes bring
two people together.
Darmok and Jalad
at Tanagra.
You and me here... at El-Adrel.
Kira at Bashi.
Temba, his arms wide.
My turn?
No, I'm not much
of a storyteller.
Besides,
you wouldn't understand.
Shaka. When the walls fell.
( sighs )
Perhaps that
doesn't matter.
You want
to hear it anyway.
There is a story--
a very ancient one
from Earth.
I'll try and remember it.
Gilgamesh, a king.
At Uruk.
He tormented his subjects.
He made them angry.
They cried out aloud
"Send us a companion
for our king.
Spare us from his madness."
Enkidu,
a wild man
from the forest
entered the city.
They fought
in the temple.
They fought in the streets.
Gilgamesh
defeated Enkidu.
They became great friends.
Gilgamesh
and Enkidu at Uruk.
At Uruk.
The new friends went out
into the desert together
where the great bull of heaven
was killing men by the hundreds.
Enkidu caught the bull
by the tail.
Gilgamesh struck him
with his sword.
Gilgamesh.
They were victorious.
But Enkidu
fell to the ground,
struck down by the gods
and Gilgamesh
wept bitter tears saying,
"He who was my companion
"through adventure
and hardship
is gone forever."
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Despite the risk of war
I have no choice
but to break the stalemate.
Phasers nearly ready, sir.
Stand by to fire, Mr. Worf.
Commander,
the Tamarian's bioscan
is becoming unreadable.
He may be dead, sir.
If we know that,
so do the Tamarians.
Riker to La Forge.
La Forge here.
I need those phasers.
Sir, sensors are tracking
the entity.
It is approaching
Captain Picard's position.
( roaring )
I understand
your sacrifice, Captain.
( roaring )
Unfortunately, if our friend
out there has its way
no one will ever know
what you tried to do.
( roaring )
DATA:
Nine meters and closing.
The energy output of the entity
has doubled, Commander.
Six meters.
La Forge to Bridge.
You have phasers.
Fire!
Their particle beam emitters
are inoperative, sir.
Scattering field is down, sir.
O'Brien, energize.
We got him, Commander.
Maximum shields.
Aye, sir.
Red alert!
Starboard shields
holding at 52%.
Forward shields are gone.
Let's get out of here.
DATA:
That may not
be possible, sir.
The starboard nacelle
has sustained a direct hit.
Warp engines are off-line.
Go to impulse.
Back us off.
They are matching our maneuver,
sir, and firing.
Return fire, Mr. Worf.
Full phasers.
Firing, sir.
Their shields are holding.
They are firing again.
Our shields have failed.
Commander, we cannot
survive another hit.
( door opening )
Hail the Tamarian vessel.
Aye, Captain.
Zinda!
His face black, his eyes red.
Temarc.
The river Temarc!
In winter.
Darmok...
And Jalad at Tanagra.
and Jalad...
on the ocean.
Sokath! His eyes open.
The beast of Tanagra?
Uzani. His army.
Shaka. When the walls fell.
Picard and Dathon at El-Adrel.
Mirab, with sails unfurled.
Temba...
his arms open.
at rest.
Thank you.
DATA:
Power has been restored, sir.
New friends, Captain?
I can't say,
Number One.
But at least
they're not new enemies.
I hope
I'm not intruding.
No, of course not,
Number One. Please.
The damage report's
ready for your review.
Thank you.
Greek, sir.
Oh...
the Homeric Hymns--
one of the root metaphors
of our own culture.
For the next time we
encounter the Tamarians?
More familiarity
with our own mythology
might help us
to relate to theirs.
The Tamarian was willing
to risk all of us
just for the hope
of communication...
connection.
Now the door is open
between our peoples.
That commitment meant more
to him than his own life.
Thank you, Number One.