There's a time when you want
to call a Romulan's bluff
and there's a time when
you don't, wouldn't you say?
Well, one does not
always have the luxury.
You've got to choose
your time and place with them.
True or false?
Yes, whenever possible.
So, this time
you were lucky.
Hmm.
Ah, I suppose...
all's well
that ends well.
But if I'd been
in your shoes...
Well, you know,
that...
really does look
very nice, Mr. Mot.
I think that will
be sufficient.
Ahh, hold on.
Hmm...
There.
You know, I must
tell you, Captain,
Will Riker was in
for a trim yesterday,
and he agrees with me
a hundred percent.
RIKER:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt.
We're receiving
an emergency distress signal
from the Solarion Four
colony.
Uh-oh, that's right along
the Cardassian border.
Lay in a new course.
I'm on my way.
I told him we shouldn't
have colonized
so close
to the Cardassians.
Report.
The signal ended
abruptly at 0455.
Unable to raise them
on subspace.
Hail them on the upper and lower
band frequencies, Mr. Worf.
I've tried.
No response.
Time to the Solarion
system?
26 minutes,
Captain.
I understand you've been
discussing alternative
adversarial engagement
strategies with Mot.
It would be more
accurate to say
he was discussing them
with me.
He's the best barber
in Starfleet.
What can you do?
Sir, receiving
another signal
of a vessel leaving orbit
of Solarion Four.
New frequency,
low band, audio only.
Open a channel.
MAN:
This is the Bajora.
We claim responsibility
for the destruction
of the Federation
colony on Solarion Four.
As long as we are
without our homeland,
no one will be safe
in this sector.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45076.3.
We have arrived
at Lya Station Alpha
with survivors from
Solarion Four.
Admiral Kennelly has
rendezvoused
to discuss the Bajoran
terrorist attack.
( coughing )
Sorry.
Ginger tea with honey,
80 degrees Celsius.
Ginger tea?
My Aunt Adele's cure
for the common cold.
Common, hell...
I picked this up from
the Cardassian liaison
this weekend.
It's some damn virus
they've sicced on me.
Did he have anything
to say about this attack?
It's the same old story
for the Cardassians.
They've had
terrorist problems
ever since they annexed
the Bajoran home world
40 years ago.
But in 40 years,
they've never attacked
a Federation target.
A new militant
splinter group
has broken away from
the Bajoran settlement camps.
Leader's name is Orta.
Apparently, he's willing
to do whatever he has to
to get attention.
And our response?
Listen, Jean-Luc.
I'm the first to say
the Bajora deserve attention.
Chased off their own planet
by the Cardassians,
forced to wander
the galaxy,
settling wherever
they can find room.
It's tragic.
On many worlds
we've been to,
they are isolated,
treated as pariahs.
The Federation is
sympathetic to their cause,
but they're not
helping themselves
with an attack
like this.
That's what I want you
to communicate to them.
But this could be
done through
diplomatic channels,
Admiral.
What do you really
want of us?
Find this
terrorist leader Orta.
Get him back
where he belongs
any way you can.
Any way I can?
The Federation has dozens
of settlements in that sector.
We cannot allow
the violence to continue.
And what do I have
to offer Orta
to might persuade him
to cooperate?
Amnesty.
Admiral...
(laughing)
And a promise
that we will
immediately begin
to address this issue
with the Cardassians.
Quietly,
behind the scenes,
using every legitimate
means possible.
But the Bajora
must be patient.
Admiral,
they've endured
generations of
sympathy and promises.
How can I believe
that this Orta
will be satisfied
with more of the same?
It's your job to see to it
that he does, Jean-Luc.
RIKER:
Riker to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
Have you approved
the transfer
of a new officer
to the Enterprise?
PICARD:
Negative.
Well, we've got one
waiting to beam aboard
complete with orders.
RIKER:
Ensign Ro Laren.
Ro Laren?
From the Wellington?
RIKER:
The very same.
Shall I tell her there's
been some mistake?
Stand by, Commander.
I wrote the orders.
I thought she might be
valuable to you.
Admiral,
respectfully,
I would appreciate
consulting rights
on the assigning
of a new officer,
especially one with
the record of Ro Laren.
She's Bajoran.
There are other Bajorans in
Starfleet, assign one of them.
I've discussed
this situation with her.
And I am convinced that she is
the right one for this job.
After what happened
on Garon Two,
she has no business
serving on any starship--
let alone the flagship,
my ship!
You're taking her,
Captain.
It's been arranged.
I can't tell you
how difficult it was
to get her
out of prison.
It's that
important to you?
It's that important
to the mission.
Picard to Riker.
RIKER:
Go ahead.
Proceed with
the transport.
Sir..?
I'll fill you in later.
Yes, sir.
I hope you and I don't
regret this, Admiral.
You can handle her,
Captain,
if anyone can.
Ensign Ro Laren reporting
as ordered, Commander.
You will follow
Starfleet uniform code
aboard this ship,
Ensign.
There will be members
of this crew who will
not want to serve
with Ensign Laren, sir.
They will have to learn
to live with it.
I intend to demand the highest
level of performance from her.
I would expect
nothing less.
It won't be
for long, will.
( door chimes )
Come.
Yes, Ensign Laren,
please sit down.
Ensign Ro, sir.
I beg your pardon?
The Bajoran custom has
the family name first,
the individual's
name second.
I am properly
addressed as Ensign Ro.
I'm sorry,
I didn't know.
No, there's
no reason you should.
It's an old custom.
Most Bajora these days
accept the distortion
of their names
in order to assimilate.
I do not.
I wish to be candid
with you, Ensign.
Please.
I'm fully aware of
your Starfleet record
your problems
on other ships,
and the incident
on Garon Two
that led to your
court-martial.
And I'm concerned
about your presence
on this
delicate mission.
I don't want to be here
any more than you
want me to be here, sir.
Then why did you take
this assignment?
If I may be
equally candid?
It's better than prison.
RIKER:
Better than prison?
There are officers who wait
years to serve on this ship.
Being called back
into Starfleet
was not my idea.
Nor ours.
Nevertheless, we will
all be serving together.
Commander Riker and I
have expectations....
Captain,
I know the routine.
You don't have
to worry about me.
We're stuck with
each other.
So let's just get this
over with as quickly as possible
and go our own
separate ways, okay?
Dismissed.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
We are approaching
the Valo system on
the outskirts
of Cardassian territory
where many Bajorans
have resettled.
There are dozens
of Bajoran camps
on the three
class M planets.
I suggest we start
on Valo Three
where an ad hoc leader
named Jas Holza lives.
The Federation has had
several dealings with him.
I met Holza
at a symposium
a few years ago.
What can you tell us
about him, Doctor?
I found him to be
a very concerned leader
and a good spokesman
for his people
and a terrific dancer.
No, really,
I'm serious.
At a... reception
afterwards.
At least this man has
genuine experience in diplomacy.
And that's a big advantage
on this mission.
Very well, Mr. Data.
Will you contact Holza
and arrange a meeting?
Sir.
Ensign Ro?
You're familiar
with the star system.
You'll take the conn.
Is there a problem,
Ensign?
You're wasting
your time.
Holza is nobody.
He's the token Bajoran that
respectable people
invite to symposiums
and diplomatic soirees,
but he has no real influence
among my people.
Ensign, whom do you
suggest we speak to?
Don't you understand?
These are
desperate people
ready to martyr
themselves.
They don't want to talk.
Well, this ship
is prepared
to defend itself
if necessary.
Oh, it will be.
Don't fool yourself.
This mission will end
in bloodshed.
Well, let's hope that
you're mistaken, Ensign.
But can you point us at
the right individual,
as Mr. Data suggested?
I would go to the camp
on the southern continent
of Valo Two.
Find a man
named Keeve Falor.
He has no diplomatic
experience,
and he won't
ask you to dance.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I read about
the achievements
of the ancient Bajoran
civilization
in my fifth grade reader.
They were architects
and artists,
builders
and philosophers
when humans were not yet
standing erect.
Now I see how history
has rewarded them.
This used to be me.
Baleekam.
Baleek, baleek!
Baleek!
Ro Laren.
It's been a long time.
Keeve Falor,
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
Commander Data,
and Lieutenant Worf.
I'm pleased
you agreed
to meet with us,
Mr. Keeve.
You honor me by the proper
use of my name, Captain.
Ensign Ro has
educated me.
Has she? I'm pleased
you still remember.
Let me show you
our camp.
We are not
a violent race, Captain.
Just passionate about
our cause,
and that passion has
led some to take up arms.
Do you know
where we can find Orta?
I'm afraid not.
Can you help us
to locate him?
I'm sorry,
I don't wish to help you.
Don't misunderstand.
I for one believe the raid
on the Federation outpost
was poor judgment.
You are innocent
bystanders,
and I cannot
condone violence
against those who are
not our enemies.
Then, I don't understand
why you're unwilling.
Because you are
innocent bystanders.
You were innocent
bystanders for decades
as the Cardassians
took our homes--
as they violated
and tortured our people
in the most hideous
ways imaginable.
As we were
forced to flee.
We were saddened
by those events,
but they occurred
within the designated borders
of the Cardassian Empire.
And the Federation is
pledged not to interfere
in the internal
affairs of others.
How convenient
that must be for you.
To turn a deaf ear
to those who suffer
behind a line
on a map.
Well, I'm not here to debate
Federation policy with you,
but I can offer you
assistance.
Simply because of
one terrorist attack?
Well, perhaps I should
have known, then.
We should have attacked
the Federation long ago.
What do you think
of that, Ro?
I think you are
a small man who feels
a rush of power
in his belly
and enjoys it
far too much, Keeve.
Stop talking
and listen.
We've had our problems
with the Cardassians, too.
But now that
we have a treaty,
we're in a position
to help.
Your people
have been forced
to resettle
all over the quadrant,
but now we can make
a legitimate case
with the Cardassians
that this is not
an isolated problem.
We can work
diplomatically
on your behalf.
But first these
terrorist attacks must end.
We live in different
universes, you and I.
Yours is about diplomacy,
politics, strategy.
Mine is about blankets.
If we were to exchange
places for one night,
you might better
understand.
Mr. Data, see that
the replicators
provide a blanket for
every man, woman and child
before nightfall.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, determine what
these people may have
in the way
of emergency needs.
And provide for them.
WORF:
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Return to your ship.
I will contact you when
I have any information
that might be
of assistance to you.
Ensign.
You were helpful.
The blankets were helpful.
Nothing I said
mattered.
In an age when
their technology
should be able to clothe
and feed all of them...
that they should
live like this.
I couldn't,
and I wouldn't.
That's one reason
I ran away.
They're lost,
defeated.
I will never be.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45077.8.
Keeve Falor has kept
his promise
and directed us towards
the third moon of Valo One
where we will meet tomorrow
with the terrorist
leader, Orta.
Do you mind
if we join you?
Yes.
I'll tell you one thing,
if I ever find myself
on an away team
with Ensign Ro,
I won't
turn my back on her.
Perhaps the Captain felt
she'd be valuable
on the mission.
That was orders.
Had to be.
She doesn't
belong here.
She doesn't even
belong in the uniform
as far as
I'm concerned.
Really?
Really.
Sounds like someone
I'd like to know.
Excuse me.
Am I disturbing you?
Yes.
Good.
You look like someone
who wants to be disturbed.
I'd rather be alone.
Oh, no, you wouldn't.
I beg your pardon.
Well, if you wanted
to be alone,
you would have stayed
in your quarters.
The only reason to come here
is to be amongst people.
Who are you?
My name is Guinan.
I tend bar,
and I listen.
Huh.
Have you heard
anything interesting?
Everyone's
talking about you.
Heard anything
interesting?
Mm-hmm.
Well, it's all true.
I believe truth is in
the eye of the beholder.
Isn't that supposed
to be beauty?
Truth, beauty-- it works
for a lot of things.
They say you never told
the true story of Galon Two.
They also say
you didn't defend yourself
at your court-martial.
What was to defend?
I didn't follow orders.
Eight members
of the away team died.
Your fault?
Yeah, my fault.
So you sit alone
in crowded rooms
staring at your drink.
I think you enjoy it.
I enjoy it?
Well, you work so hard
at torturing yourself.
I can only think
you must enjoy it.
Who are you?
I told you,
I'm Guinan.
I tend bar,
and I listen.
Well, you're not like any
bartender I ever met before.
And you're not like
any Starfleet officer
I've ever met before,
but that sounds
like the beginning
of a very interesting
friendship.
I don't stay anywhere
long enough to make friends.
Too late.
You just did.
Excuse me.
FEMALE VOICE:
Bridge to Ensign Ro.
Go ahead.
Subspace communication
coming in for you, Ensign.
Thank you.
Computer, direct subspace
transmission to monitor.
Your report, Ensign.
Everything is going exactly
as you predicted, Admiral.
Any indication of weapons
or vessels beneath the surface?
The composition of the moon's
surface is blocking the sensors.
Which is very likely
why they chose this moon
for their base
of operations.
We're on
a timetable here.
Where's Ro?
Picard to Ensign Ro.
Computer,
locate ensign Ro.
COMPUTER:
Ensign Ro is not on board
the Enterprise.
Check
the transport log.
She beamed down almost
six hours ago, sir.
Any activity
at the meeting site?
No, sir,
they didn't show up.
What the hell is
going on?
Prepare to transport us
to the same location
Ensign Ro beamed to.
Mr. Worf, phasers.
I'm picking up molecular
displacement traces.
That suggests
movement in this area
during the last
ten hours.
See if we can determine
their direction.
Standard
search pattern.
Maintain tricorder
security link.
Mr. Worf,
you come with me.
Data, I'm picking up energy
fluctuations over here.
Troi to Picard.
Captain, acknowledge.
Data to Picard.
Data to Worf.
Hold it.
Captain Picard.
I am Orta.
Please forgive
my appearance.
Unfortunately,
some years ago
as a guest
of the Cardassians,
my face was mutilated.
My vocal cords
were cut.
It was not necessary
to abduct us.
I am sorry,
but after speaking
with Ro Laren,
I decided that it was.
Then she has done us
both a disservice.
I am committed to peace.
I am not at all
interested in peace
and I am not convinced
that you are either.
Captain, I did not come here
to undermine this mission.
Whatever your motives,
you've already done
enough to damage
these negotiations.
I came here to convince these
people to listen to you.
I didn't want this
to end in bloodshed.
There will be
no bloodshed.
You don't know
all the facts, sir.
Then perhaps you would
share them with me.
All is not what it seems
to be, captain.
Perhaps someone is
using you to get to me.
Perhaps you are a victim
of this deception as well.
I do not know.
Deception?
Your mission was to seek out
the Bajoran terrorists
who destroyed the Federation
settlement on Solarion Four.
Yes.
As I have informed
Ro Laren,
it was not the Bajora.
He admits responsibility
for dozens of attacks
on Cardassian targets.
Why should we believe him
about Solarion Four?
He has
no reason to lie.
He fears
our reprisal.
I perceived no fear
or deception from him.
If they did not attack
Solarion Four, then who did?
And why would anyone want
to falsely implicate the Bajora?
Perhaps someone wanted
to draw us into the conflict.
But what would anyone
gain by doing that?
PICARD:
Ensign Ro.
May I see you
in my ready room?
Yes, sir.
You do not leave this ship
without authorization.
Captain,
I'm sorry, but...
This is not
a discussion.
You're restricted
to your quarters
for the remainder of
this mission, dismissed.
( door chimes )
What?
Hello.
It's me, Guinan.
I heard
you got grounded.
I really don't feel
like talking right now.
Come on.
Sure you do.
Why is it every time
I tell you something,
you tell me I mean
the exact opposite?
Because you're
one of those people
who's got their poles
reversed.
Do you want
to talk about it?
It's nothing
you can help me with.
Well, how do you know
until you try?
Look, I got myself
into this.
I'm just trying to figure
a way out, that's all.
Without anyone
getting killed this time.
Seems like everybody's
just pulling my strings,
you know, like I've got
no control.
Hmm.
For people
like you and me--
who have lost
their homes--
sometimes that's
the way life feels.
I'm in trouble.
There's more going on here
than anybody
on this ship realizes.
It's more than I know
how to deal with,
and I really don't know
who to trust anymore.
Including yourself?
Oh, especially myself.
Hmm.
You know,
a very long time ago,
I got into some serious
trouble too--
and I mean serious--
and I'd probably
still be there
if I hadn't
trusted one man.
( door chimes )
Come.
Ensign Ro has some things
she'd like to talk to you about.
Ensign Ro has been
confined
to her quarters.
Well, she can go
back to her quarters
when she's done.
Guinan, I don't know why you
are involved in this, but...
She's my friend.
Please sit down.
Guinan is
very selective
about whom
she calls a friend.
Sir, when I finish telling you
what I have to tell you,
I'm probably gonna
end up back in the stockade
one way or the other,
and if that's the way
it has to be, then...
I just can't
do this anymore.
What can you not do
anymore, Ensign?
Admiral Kennelly
came to me in prison
and told me he'd arrange
to get me out
if I'd go
on a mission.
I know that part.
No, sir.
Not this mission.
One for him
and only him.
You were being sent
to talk, to negotiate.
The admiral knew
that was hopeless.
My job was to give Orta
an incentive.
What kind
of incentive?
One that
you couldn't offer.
One that Starfleet
couldn't offer.
Orta was to end the terrorism
against the Federation
and return with
his people to the camps.
In exchange,
he would get
weapons, ships.
Things that would
really make a difference
against the Cardassians
in the future.
I find that
impossible to believe.
That Admiral Kennelly
would consider
supplying weapons
to the terrorists.
If you ask him,
he'll deny it.
But it's true.
I didn't leave the ship without
authorization, Captain.
I received it from
the admiral last night.
You have been in contact
with Admiral Kennelly
during this mission?
Yes, sir.
The subspace log can confirm
that part of it,
at least.
Arming these people
is a violation
of everything that
the Federation stands for.
Even you cannot
be blind to that.
No, sir, I'm not.
but this was something
I had to do.
You see, Captain,
when I was
seven years old,
I was given a piece
of sugar candy.
And I was led
by a Cardassian
into a room where
my father was sitting.
And he looked at me
with eyes I'd never seen.
The Cardassian began
to ask him questions.
And during
the next two hours,
as I was forced
to watch...
my father was tortured
until he died.
And I remember
feeling...
so ashamed of him
as he begged for mercy.
I was ashamed of him
for being weak.
I was ashamed
of being Bajoran.
Later I began
to understand
how misguided
those feelings were,
and...
and yet somehow they have
remained a part of me.
I don't want to be ashamed of
my heritage any longer, Captain.
I serve the Federation,
but I am Bajoran.
A Starfleet admiral
presented me
with an opportunity to help
my people in their fight
against
the Cardassians.
I had to accept.
Have you made
this offer to Orta?
No.
After he told me the Bajora
hadn't attacked Solarion Four,
nothing made sense anymore--
I decided to wait
until I could figure out
what was going on.
That was a wise
choice, Ensign.
It probably saved you
from another court-martial.
Have you briefed
Admiral Kennelly
since we returned
from the surface?
No, sir.
Captain, I don't know
who to trust anymore.
But that strange
bartender of yours
has a way of getting
to you, and...
and she said that
you were her friend.
Then we have
one thing in common.
Do you think that Orta
would cooperate with us
to determine
the truth here?
I think I can
persuade him to.
Good.
Our orders were
to find him,
to bring him
back to the camps
any way we could.
Perhaps that's exactly
what we should do.
And then what?
And then watch
what happens.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
I have become
convinced that
we are somehow involved
in a conspiracy.
I'm hopeful
the purpose behind it
will be revealed
in the next few hours.
Well done,
Captain.
It was a team effort,
Admiral.
Ensign Ro was
invaluable.
Good.
What's the next step?
The Enterprise will
escort a Bajoran
Antares-class cruiser
to the Valo Three camp
at 0500 hours.
Orta and his people
will be on board.
Good. Keep us advised
of your progress.
Acknowledged.
How's that Cardassian
virus, Admiral?
A lot better.
Thank you.
I'm pleased.
We'll report as soon as
our mission is accomplished.
Picard out.
RIKER:
Ensign Ro, take us
to the designated
coordinates.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Data,
keep an eye
on the Cardassian border.
Aye, sir.
The Bajoran vessel is moving up
from the surface, Captain.
On screen.
Hail them, Mr. Worf.
Audio channel open.
The ship does not have
visual capabilities.
This is Captain Picard.
We are prepared to escort you
to Valo Three.
BAJORAN WOMAN:
Acknowledged, Captain.
Be advised that our ship is
limited to half impulse.
Ensign Ro, set a course for
Valo Three, half impulse.
Aye, sir.
I am monitoring
increased activity
inside Cardassian space.
Two ships moving
along the border
heading 142.051.
Can you identify the class
of those ships, Mr. Worf?
Cardassian warships,
Galor class, Type-3.
Top of the line.
They are moving into a course
parallel to our own, Captain.
Yellow alert.
Continue
to monitor them.
Ensign Ro,
what's the closest we come
to the Cardassian border
at our current heading
to Valo Three?
13,400 kilometers, sir.
RIKER:
E.T.A.?
RO:
Eight minutes.
That's where
it will be.
The Cardassian ships are
changing course, sir.
They are crossing
the border.
They're increasing power
to their forward weapons grid.
Red alert.
Ensign Ro,
set a course
to intercept
the Cardassians.
Mr. Worf, open a channel
to the Bajoran vessel.
Open.
This is the Enterprise.
We are moving to intercept
two Cardassian warships.
Maintain your present
course and speed.
BAJORAN:
Acknowledged, Enterprise.
The Cardassians are
within visual range.
On screen.
WORF:
They are hailing us, sir.
Open a channel,
Mr. Worf.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
How can we help you?
Gul Dolak,
Cardassian militia four one.
We have no argument
with you, Captain.
I'm pleased to hear
that, Gul Dolak.
All of us
in the Federation
value our peaceful relations
with our Cardassian neighbors.
No more than
we value the relations
with our Federation
neighbors.
Well, now that
we've established
our mutual goodwill,
what's on your mind?
We have identified
the Bajoran ship
you are escorting
as a terrorist carrier.
Terrorist carrier?
Are you certain?
Most certain, Captain.
It has committed
many crimes against us.
We know
its markings well.
Well, rest assured,
Gul Dolak,
there will be
no terrorist attacks today.
We are escorting
the Bajoran settlers
to their camp on
Valo Three.
You can monitor
their course if you wish.
We would request that
you withdraw
and leave
the matter to us.
This is neutral space,
Gul Dolak.
You have
no jurisdiction here.
Nor do you.
If we withdraw,
what do you intend to do
with the Bajoran vessel?
We intend
to destroy it.
I see.
That puts me in
a difficult position.
I've promised to escort
these people to their camps.
You are protecting the enemies
of the Cardassian people.
If you do not withdraw,
we will take great offense.
I'm sorry to offend you,
Gul Dolak,
but we cannot
withdraw.
We are prepared to take
any steps necessary.
Is that intended
as a threat?
It is a complaint...
from your Cardassian
neighbors.
You have
one hour to withdraw.
Advise Starfleet
of our status, Mr. Data.
When Admiral Kennelly calls,
I'll speak to him
in my ready room.
It seemed, Admiral,
that they knew our course,
our destination,
our plan.
I'm sure they monitor
the border at all times
for terrorist
activity.
Their sensors must have
picked up Orta's ship,
that's all.
I'm not convinced of that.
The important thing
is what do we do now.
Do you have any
suggestions, Admiral?
Your top priority is
to protect
the Cardassian treaty.
Sir, I see no way to protect
the Cardassian peace
without sacrificing
the Bajoran.
If that's your call,
I'll support it.
No. I'm not willing
to give them up.
I don't think you're looking
at the big picture, Jean-Luc.
We can't afford to lose
the Cardassian treaty.
Well, I just see a different
big picture, Admiral.
It looks something
like this--
I see
the Cardassian liaison
with his
Cardassian virus
coming to meet with you
after the attack
on Solarion Four.
"Now we have a common enemy,"
he says.
The Bajoran terrorists.
The Cardassians
can't find them,
but maybe
the Federation can.
I am beginning
to see...
that our mission has,
in fact, been to expose Orta
so that the Cardassians
can move in
and destroy him.
I think you've lost
your perspective, Captain.
We'll discuss this further
when you return.
For now, I'm giving you
a direct order to withdraw.
Kennelly out.
Ensign Ro, set a course
bearing 187.102.
One-quarter impulse.
Aye, sir.
He's ordered us
to withdraw?
The Cardassians are moving
toward the Bajoran vessel,
Captain.
Hold present course.
The Bajoran ship
has been destroyed.
Subspace signal coming in
from Starfleet, Captain.
Admiral Kennelly.
On screen.
It is on a secure
channel, sir.
In your ready room?
No.
Here.
On screen.
Report.
The Cardassians
have destroyed
the Bajoran ship,
Admiral.
All hands lost?
PICARD:
No, sir.
Survivors?
No one was on board.
What are you talking
about?
The ship was controlled
from the ground.
Communication
was handled through
a subspace relay
on the vessel.
This was your idea,
Picard?
Actually, no.
This was Ensign Ro's idea,
but I fully endorsed it--
I suspected that
something like this
might occur.
They're terrorists,
damn it.
Why in the hell would
you want to protect them?
Admiral,
I am more concerned
with protecting the honor
and integrity of Starfleet.
Do you know how many
of our people
they killed
on Solarion Four?
The Bajorans did not attack
Solarion Four.
Who told you that?
Orta?
PICARD:
Yes.
And you believed him?
Admiral, Orta's ships are
old and obsolete.
They don't even
have warp capabilities.
They couldn't have reached
another star system,
let alone
attacked one.
Then who is
responsible?
I'd suggest that
you ask your friend,
the Cardassian liaison,
Admiral.
The only explanation
I can think of...
is that the Cardassians
staged it.
The Cardassians? Why?
Perhaps they were hoping
to find someone in Starfleet
like you, Admiral,
naive enough to solve
their Bajoran problem for them.
What will
happen to him?
I'm not sure.
A hearing, certainly.
Probably
a court-martial.
Well, if he gets sent
to the stockade on Jaros Two,
tell him to request
a room in the east wing.
The west wing gets awfully
hot in the afternoons.
How soon do you
intend to return
to Lya Station
Alpha, sir?
In a few weeks.
We have some surveying
to do in sector 21305.
Perhaps
I should arrange
for some other
transportation back.
Ensign,
you were recruited
for one mission,
and if you wish to be
relieved of further duty,
I can certainly
arrange it.
But I'd like you to consider
remaining in Starfleet.
You're not serious.
Mm-hmm.
I think it would be
a shame for Starfleet
to lose someone
of your potential.
Well, thank you,
Captain...
but this uniform...
it just doesn't fit,
and you know it.
That can change.
I don't think so.
I've noticed
qualities in you
that could be
harnessed, molded.
Don't count on it.
I think you've got a great deal
to learn from Starfleet.
I always thought Starfleet had
a lot to learn from me, Captain.
That's an attitude
that I have found common
among the best officers
I've ever served with.
But you're not
one of them yet.
But you could be,
if you work at it.
That's an interesting
challenge,
and I rarely refuse
an interesting challenge.
There would have
to be one condition.
Condition?
Picard to Enterprise.
Two to beam up.