The hospital facility
will be located there.
Facing north
in that grove of trees.
And the school
and the art center
will be standing there,
centrally located
among the residential pods.
Very good.
At this rate, we can bring
the next wave of colonists in
in about six months.
I've got to tell you,
I envy you.
This is a beautiful place
to put down roots.
Somehow, Riker,
you don't strike me
as the kind that
puts down roots.
No? How do I strike you?
As a free spirit.
As an adventurer.
An adventurer?
Aren't you pioneers
all adventurers at heart?
Of course,
but we also have
this nesting instinct.
It's exciting
to find a new world,
but the joy comes
in making it a home--
building houses,
having children.
Very interesting.
I'd love to discuss this
further with you.
Dinner tonight?
If you want to share
camp rations in my tent,
I'd be delighted.
Haven't we gotten you
a replicator yet?
No, we haven't.
But I've been saving up my
ration of dried chicken curry.
It should go nicely
with that bottle of wine
I happen to know
you brought with you.
This is sounding better
all the time.
And as you know...
I provide the most
memorable desserts.
My favorite part of dinner.
DR. CRUSHER:
Will, Carmen.
We've been going over
the schematics for the hospital.
The location seems fine.
When the Enterprise
comes back tomorrow,
we'll get a crew
started on that.
( loud whirring )
Carmen, have you got
construction started
I didn't know about?
No.
What is that?
Data?
I do not recognize
the sound.
I believe it is
coming from above.
Will, what is it?
Data, what's our
best bet for cover?
Subterranean caverns
to the east, sir. Doctor?
Will...
Start gathering
everyone together.
We've seen this before.
We know what it is.
Now get moving.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Follow him!
Let's go!
Come on! Come on!
Follow him!
No! Stay together!
Stay together! This way!
This way! This way!
I've got him!
Will!
Help us!
Data!
Carmen!
Captain, censors indicate
a disturbance
near the outpost
on Melona IV.
What kind of
disturbance?
I cannot tell.
We are still too far away.
It could be
an electrical storm.
See if you can
contact the colony.
WORF: Aye, sir.
Captain, there is no response
from Melona colony,
but the disturbance in
the atmosphere is increasing.
How far are we?
At current speed, 27 hours.
Bridge to La Forge.
La Forge here, Captain.
Are you picking up
any readings from Melona?
Yes, sir.
Something strange is going on.
There are violent disruptions
in the atmosphere.
Ensign, increase
to warp eight.
Come on!
Keep moving!
Watch your step,
but keep moving.
RIKER:
Let's go. Let's go.
Keep moving.
Deep into the cave.
Come on.
Be careful.
Deep into the cave.
Keep moving.
How much protection
will this cave give us?
The refractory metal
in the rock formation
may act
an effective barrier.
Let's seal off
this entrance.
Let's hope there's
enough air in here.
There's got to be
a ventilation source somewhere.
We need some light.
How are the others?
Uh, just scrapes
and bruises, I think.
I'll check further.
Where's Carmen?
She didn't make it.
She was trying to save
an old man who had fallen.
I'm sorry.
I think we're going to be
all right in here.
I'm not sure about
the air supply, so stay put.
Don't move around.
Don't expend
any unnecessary energy.
With any luck, we'll be able
to wait this thing out.
Riker to Enterprise.
Commander, the refractory
metal in the rock strata
may also interfere
with communication.
Data, we've only seen the
Crystalline Entity once before.
How do you know these metals
will protect us?
I'm not entirely certain
they will, sir.
I was afraid you were going to
say something like that.
WORF:
Sir, the disturbance on Melona
is becoming more intense.
Keep hailing them.
All channels, Mr. Worf.
Captain, the fact that
they're not responding
doesn't necessarily mean
there's anything wrong.
The atmospheric disturbance
could be jamming the signal.
I know, Counselor.
Still no response, sir.
Increase to warp nine.
How long, Mr. Worf?
WORF: Six hours.
I've got one man unconscious.
We can't stay in here
much longer.
If we open that entrance
and it's still out there,
we're dead.
If we all stay in here,
It has been over an hour
since we heard the entity, sir.
It may be gone.
Or it may be waiting
out there for us.
( rumbling )
Everybody stay here.
WORF:
Commander.
Commander Riker,
are you there?
Lieutenant Worf,
I don't think I've ever
seen a more beautiful sight.
It's good to see
you're all right, Commander.
What happened here?
The Crystalline Entity
paid us a visit.
We lost two colonists,
but we got the rest in here.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45122.3:
We have notified
Starfleet Command
of our intention
to pursue and investigate
the Crystalline Entity.
To that end, we have been
joined by Dr. Kila Marr,
a xenologist who has made
studying the entity
her life's work.
Welcome to the Enterprise.
I'm Commander William Riker.
Commander, Dr. Kila Marr.
We're glad you're here.
You were on the surface
during the attack?
That's right.
Remarkable.
You and your group
are the only known beings
ever to survive an assault
by the Crystalline Entity.
We were lucky.
I should say.
And your android,
he was there, too?
Lieutenant Commander Data
was there, yes.
Well, shall we get started?
I'll be glad to show you
to your quarters.
Oh, Commander,
a chance to talk
to survivors so soon
after an attack?
I've been waiting
years for this.
I don't want to waste
a moment more.
...and when we came out of the
cave, there was nothing left.
Everywhere we looked,
there was complete devastation.
Trees gone.
Nothing.
That's typical.
It could take years
for anything to grow again.
DATA:
Doctor, I ran a full
spectrographic analysis,
section by section,
trace elements confirm
it is the same entity
which destroyed the colony
on Omicron Theta.
The Crystalline Entity
seems to function
like a gigantic
electromagnetic collector.
It needs a lot of power
to keep going,
so it strips every form of life
from the worlds it encounters
and converts it all
into energy.
There was no vegetation, no
insects, not even soil bacteria.
It left nothing.
Except witnesses
for the first time
in 11 recorded attacks.
Now, why, I wonder,
did it spare your group?
It didn't spare
everyone, Doctor.
If you'll check your records,
you'll find that two of
the colonists did not survive.
My point is
that until now,
there have never been
any survivors.
DATA: Doctor, the cave in which
we hid was made of rock
which contained
heavy concentrations
of kelbonite
and fistrium.
We surmise
that the entity
was unable to
penetrate that barrier.
I would like to do interviews
with each of the survivors.
Collect as much
specific detail as I can
from their observations.
Of course.
And I'd like to inspect
the remains in Melona colony
as soon as possible.
Commander Data,
you will accompany the Doctor
to the surface.
Yes, sir--
If you don't mind, Captain,
I prefer to choose my own team.
Doctor, there is
no one on this ship
with more knowledge
of the Crystalline Entity
than Commander Data.
He originated
on Omicron Theta.
I am aware of his origins.
I'm very much aware
that his brother Lore
worked with
the Crystalline Entity,
led it to Omicron Theta,
where it killed
every living thing.
I don't think
it's unreasonable
that I should prefer
to make another choice.
You may request
additional team members,
but in the best interests
of this investigation,
I think you should work
with Commander Data.
As you wish, Captain.
Well?
I don't think you need an empath
to sense that woman's feelings.
There's hostility
that she seems
to have transferred
from Lore to Data.
Perhaps you shouldn't have
forced them together so soon.
If her discomfort is going
to affect her judgment
or her objectivity,
I need to know now.
Doctor,
there is evidence
of residual bitrious matter
in the soil.
It was not present
before the entity's attack.
Doctor?
Dr. Marr,
you have made it clear
that my presence disturbs you.
However, I do not see
how we can achieve our task
if you continue
to ignore me.
Commander, I can hear
everything you say to me.
If there is anything
worth my response,
you can be sure
I will not be silent.
Then I do not understand
your lack of interest
in the bitrious filament
I mentioned.
It's old news to me.
I found evidence of bitrium
on the last three attack sites.
It seems to be a residual
that the entity produces
after it absorbs
living matter.
I'm actually more
interested in this cave.
It still amazes me
that your group was spared.
As I have speculated,
the presence of refractory...
Refractory metals--
yes, I know.
On two separate occasions,
settlers sought refuge
in caves--
some of them deeper
than this one.
They perished anyway.
Were those caves laced
with kelbonite or fistrium?
The tunnels on Forlat III
had strong deposits
of kelbonite, yes.
Then perhaps the combination
of the two metals prevented...
Perhaps it was you.
I do not understand.
Maybe it was your presence
that made the entity
pass over the people
in this cave.
Did that occur to you?
I cannot see what effect
my being here would have had...
If you had been in contact
with the entity--
if that's the reason
Melona was attacked--
it surely wouldn't have
killed its ally.
You believe that
I lured the entity here?
Did you?
No, Doctor.
Because Lore betrayed
the colonists on Omicron Theta,
you believe that I am capable
of the same behavior.
You are mistaken, Doctor.
My programming is distinctly
different from Lore's.
You don't understand,
I am accusing you
of collaborating
with that monster.
I do understand,
and I am attempting to explain
to you it is impossible.
It's amazing.
You can't feel anything,
can you?
Nothing I say to you
hurts you.
That is true, Doctor.
I'm getting a slight elevation
of monocaladium particulates
in this cave wall--
are you making note of it?
Yes, Doctor.
My son died on Omicron Theta.
He was 16 when
the colony was attacked.
That is the reason
I have become an expert
on the Crystalline Entity.
I have spent my life
studying it,
tracking it and hoping
one day to find it.
And if I learn that
you have been helping that thing
in any way whatsoever,
I will see to it
that you are disassembled
piece by piece.
Okay, Doctor,
we've input all the data
you collected on the surface.
Just a minute, Commander.
I have some cellulose
readings from soil samples
that weren't included.
You handle that unit
like a veteran, Doctor.
One thing about
spending your life
gathering information--
you learn your way
around computers.
Hydrocarbons slightly elevated,
bitrious filaments
in trace amounts.
Lanthanides...
nitrates...
all normal.
Nothing different.
Everything falls
within the parameters
I established
at the other attack sites.
Were you expecting a different
result this time, Doctor?
I've never surveyed a site
so soon after an attack.
I thought I'd find
something new--
something that would
make a difference.
Doctor, have you ever
scanned your samples
for gamma radiation?
Why would I do that?
We are seeing
high-energy reactions
that may show up
in a gamma scan.
And if they do,
we might find a pattern,
a kind of marker left
behind by the entity.
That's a good idea, Data.
Frankly, I just don't see
what that would get us.
If the entity left
a residual trace
of anti-proton in
the samples we collected,
a gamma radiation scan
would reveal that.
Getting that
readout now, Data.
If we try
a logarithmic scale,
we will have
better resolution.
GEORDI:
There it is. See it?
DATA: Yes.
Doctor?
A sharp spike at ten K.E.V.
Another...
a pattern.
So we know the entity
leaves anti-protons behind.
If it also deposits
anti-protons in space
as it travels,
can we detect them?
Sure, we can set
the ship's lateral sensors
for gamma radiation.
Well, let's get to it,
shall we?
It seems I owe you
thanks, Commander.
The thanks actually go to a
Dr. Clendenning of Omicron Theta
who did the first experiments
with gamma scans.
I never read that.
It wasn't in any of his records.
That is correct,
but I possess
much of his knowledge.
He was working
on new detectors
at the time of the attack
on Omicron Theta.
I'd heard
you'd been programmed
with the experiences
of the colonists,
but frankly, I find it
hard to believe.
Bridge.
It is true, Doctor.
The contents of
their logs and journals
were transferred
into my memory cells.
The man who created me
also experimented
with scanning
the synaptic patterns
of the colonists'
temporal lobes
and programming them
into my neural nets.
You possess their thoughts?
To some degree.
Dr. Soong hoped to provide me
with an amalgam
of the colonists' memories.
Interesting.
DR. MARR:
There-- a spike at ten K.E.V.
And again.
It's the same pattern
we saw in Engineering.
Mr. Data, can you project
a course from it?
DATA: Yes, sir.
There are two
possible destinations--
the Brechtian Cluster
and the Argos system.
Is either populated?
Yes, sir.
The Brechtian Cluster
has two inhabited planets.
Ensign, set a course
for the Brechtian Cluster.
Captain, I've done
some preliminary estimates
on a firing pattern
we need to destroy the entity.
The photon torpedoes
will require some reprogramming,
but with your permission,
I'll give the calculations
to Lieutenant Worf.
Reprogram the torpedoes,
Mr. Worf.
But let's hope
we don't have to use them.
I beg your pardon?
If we can possibly avoid
firing on it...
Aren't you going to kill it?
Perhaps you should join me
in my Ready Room.
I don't understand.
Why are we pursuing the entity
if not to destroy it?
We're not hunters, Doctor,
nor is it our role
to exact revenge.
What do you propose?
We track it down,
greet it warmly,
and ask it if it would mind
terribly not ravaging
any more planets?
I don't deny that it may
be necessary to fire on it,
but I look on that
as a last resort.
Why? Why not just kill it?
I want to try
to communicate with it.
What?
We know from
our own experience
that our shields
will protect us.
So long as we are
in no danger,
I will make every effort
to communicate.
To what end?
If we can determine
what its needs are,
we might find other sources
to supply it.
Its needs are to slaughter
people by the thousands.
It is nothing
but a giant killing machine.
Doctor,
the sperm whale on Earth
devours millions of cuttlefish
as it roams the oceans.
It is not evil.
It is feeding.
The same may be true
of the entity.
That would be small comfort for
those who have died defeated.
We're not talking
about cuttlefish.
We're talking about people.
I would argue that
the Crystalline Entity
has as much right
to be here as we do.
Now, Commander Data
has some theories
on how we might communicate.
Please confer with him.
( classical music )
( door chiming )
Come in.
Am I disturbing you?
Not at all, Doctor.
Commander, there's
something I want to say.
You have been helpful
to me and kind,
and I repaid you
with accusations,
and I realize
I may have been wrong.
That is very gracious of you
to say, Doctor,
but I have not
been injured by you.
Captain Picard has told me
you've done work
in trying to establish
communication with the entity.
That is true.
I have experimented with
producing vibrations in crystals
by means of graviton pulses.
Like tapping on
a crystal goblet.
Exactly.
I will call up the results
I have achieved thus far
for you to study.
All right.
Commander,
just what kind of memories
do you retain of
the colonists?
I do not possess the
minute-to-minute remembrances
of each person,
although the more
intense recollections
are contained
in my memory banks.
Do you have any of
my son's memories?
Marr... Raymond.
Called "Renny."
Yes, I do.
I see.
And his journals?
Yes.
I was wondering...
do you know...
did he blame me?
Blame you?
For going away.
For leaving him
on Omicron Theta.
There are no records
of any blame against you.
I left him with friends.
I chose to pursue
my own career.
I planned to go back,
but things kept interfering.
I kept thinking,
"I'll go next month"...
but there weren't
any more next months.
There are no records
of any negative thoughts
about you.
His personal journals
indicated that he was proud
that you were such
a fine scientist.
He was?
What else do you know?
RIKER:
Commander Data, Dr. Marr,
report to the Bridge
immediately.
MAN: We are being chased
by an unidentified entity
traveling at warp speed...
A distress call from a ship
called the Kallisko.
It's being pursued
by an unknown object.
MAN: Sensors indicate
a crystalline structure
of indeterminate mass.
PICARD: How strong are
your shields, Captain?
MAN: We are a transport ship.
Our shields are minimal.
Do you carry weapons?
MAN:
Only low-level particle phasers.
Do you know
what this being is?
Kallisko, change course.
Take evasive action.
Do whatever you can
to outrun it.
MAN:
We are under attack!
( screaming )
Captain, notify our people
on Boreal III.
( screaming )
( silence )
Mr. Worf,
try to re-establish.
I cannot, sir.
There is no response.
DATA:
The Crystalline Entity
is moving away, sir.
PICARD:
Ensign, set a course
for the Kallisko.
Mr. Riker,
prepare an away team.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45125.7:
An away team
led by Commander Riker
has conducted a thorough survey
of the alien ship Kallisko
and has returned to
the Enterprise to report.
Pretty much as we expected,
sir, no survivors.
Not a trace of anything
that was ever alive--
not even a seed
in their greenery storage.
Warp and impulse engines
are down, sir, but they
can be restarted.
A skeleton crew could take
the ship to a Starbase.
No, we don't have time
for that now.
Mr. Worf, send a message
to the nearest Starbase.
Ask them to dispatch a crew.
Aye, sir.
PICARD: Mr. La Forge,
make certain that we're
still picking up
the gamma radiation patterns
of the entity.
Aye, sir.
Have you and Commander Data
made any progress
in finding a means
of communication?
I believe so. There are
some things to iron out.
Please keep working at it.
We may need it soon.
Deck 17.
Doctor, you've
seemed preoccupied
since we surveyed
the Kallisko.
I've found it easy
to talk to you, Commander.
Do you mind
if I tell you something?
Not at all.
After hearing the screams
of those men,
I-I've found it hard
not to think about my son...
about what happened to him.
I've read stories
about soldiers
in the battlefield--
wounded... dying.
They call out for their mothers,
And I've often wondered if
my son called out for me.
If, uh,
he died wondering
why I didn't come to him.
( door opens )
( door chimes )
Come.
It's still headed for
the Brechtian Cluster.
We've reestablished
our course.
Very well.
Oh, one thing,
Number One--
Starfleet will be notifying
Carmen Davila's parents
of her death
and returning
her personal effects.
Would you care to
enclose a letter?
Yes, sir.
I'd like that very much.
Is there something more,
Number One?
Permission
to speak freely, sir?
Of course.
I've been thinking
maybe Dr. Marr is right.
Maybe we should
destroy the entity.
Why do you think that?
It's already killed thousands.
It will undoubtedly continue
to kill unless we stop it.
I don't want those deaths
on my conscience.
Are you sure that
that's it, Number One?
Or are you being influenced
by personal feelings?
With all due respect, sir,
I'm not a raw cadet.
I've lost people
on missions before.
If we take time to try
to communicate with this thing,
we may lose our chance
to destroy it.
And I don't think
we can risk that.
I think I'll go write that
letter to Carmen's family.
We should program
the Bridge science station
to vary the emissions
we direct toward the entity.
I'll write a subroutine
that will allow us
to change the frequency
of the graviton beam.
Data...
you told me you carried
some of my son's memories.
That is correct, Doctor.
What can you tell me
about Renny?
What were those thoughts?
Was he... happy at all
on Omicron Theta?
I have some
vivid memories of
sporting events.
He played Parrises Squares
with a group of his schoolmates.
Renny started Parrises Squares
when he was young--
too young, really--
but the older children
kept asking him to play
and I couldn't
keep him away.
He had this natural gift.
Yes.
He was pleased to have won
a championship emblem.
He wrote me about that.
He was so proud.
I'm characterizing pulse
widths in nanoseconds.
Sound right to you?
Yes, Doctor.
Your son's most
intense memories
revolve around
a young woman named Janina.
A girlfriend?
Oh, I never knew about that.
Of course,
the last person he would tell
would be his mother.
What was she like?
He enjoyed her kindness...
her gentleness...
her physical attributes.
There.
Now we can vary
all the parameters
directly from the Bridge.
Yes, Doctor.
Could you do
something for me?
It would mean a lot.
I would be happy
to be of help.
You see, all I have
left of Renny--
the only connection
I have of him--
is there,
inside your head.
I was wondering if you
would talk to me in his voice.
I know you have
the ability
to sound like other people,
isn't that right?
That is true, Doctor,
but what would you have me say?
Maybe something
from his journals?
Many of his journal entries
took the form of letters
to family and friends.
I could access
one of those.
( voice of adolescent boy )
I took my last exam today.
I think I did all right
on everything except
cellular biology.
I know you think
it's important, Mom,
but I don't see how I'm ever
going to use that stuff.
In a couple of weeks,
a bunch of us are going
on an archaeological dig
in the mountains.
The Wallaces said
it would be all right
as long as we had
adult supervision.
So don't worry, Mom.
They're looking out for me.
They're really great people,
and I like them a lot,
but they're
kind of serious.
They don't have
your sense of humor, Mom.
Mom... I miss you.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45129.2:
We are still in pursuit
of the Crystalline Entity.
Data and Doctor Marr
are prepared to attempt
communication with the being
when we intercept it.
I will admit to some
uncertainty about the prospect.
It could prove to be
a scientific triumph
or a catastrophe.
Commander,
the Brechtian Cluster
is now five
light years away.
Are we still picking up
the entity's pattern?
Yes, Commander.
But sensors have not yet locked
on to it's exact whereabouts.
Captain, we are
reasonably sure
it's between here
and the Brechtian Cluster.
If I start emitting
the graviton beam now,
it may serve as a lure,
a kind of beacon.
Make it so.
We'll start with a pulse width
of five nanoseconds--
frequency,
one pulse per second.
Commencing graviton
emissions... now.
No change
in sensor readings.
Let's ramp the frequency.
Emissions now at
ten pulses per second.
Sir.
What is it?
Do you have something?
A large mass
approaching at warp speed.
Full stop.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
Doctor, continue
emitting the signals.
Mr. Worf, on screen.
Shields up.
PICARD:
Magnify.
It's beautiful.
What's it doing?
Checking us out?
Possibly.
Just as we're
checking it out.
Dr. Marr, do you wish
to change the frequency?
Dr. Marr?
Yes, yes,
proceed, Commander.
Changing to 20 pulses
per second.
Is it responding
to us?
MARR:
Let's test that.
Ramp the frequency again,
Commander.
Emissions now at
30 pulses per second.
Captain, I'm reading
a transmission from the entity--
a series of graviton pulses.
It's working.
That's a response
to our signal.
Remarkable.
Captain, there is a pattern
emerging from the signals.
It's trying
to communicate with us.
DATA:
I believe so, sir,
but it will take some time
to decipher the patterns.
Then it's possible--
communication,
understanding.
Let me try something else.
A continuous graviton beam.
All graviton pulses
from the entity have stopped.
Maybe it doesn't like
what we're doing.
Doctor, return to
the intermittent signal.
Doctor?
Dr. Marr?
Dr. Marr, we must return
to the intermittent signal.
Counselor?
Something's very wrong,
Captain.
The entity is
beginning to resonate.
Vibrations
are increasing.
Dr. Marr,
stop the transmission.
That is an order.
Dr. Marr,
do you hear me?
It's for you, Renny.
I did it for you.
Mr. Data, shut down
the transmission.
Vibration amplitude
is increasing.
It can't last much longer.
I cannot stop
the graviton signal, Captain.
Dr. Marr has isolated
the access code.
Maybe I can create
an override sequence.
Shut it down from here.
DATA: The amplitude is
still rising, Captain.
Resonance is
approaching critical.
I can override her program, but
it's going to take some time.
Mr. Worf, will you escort
the Doctor to her quarters?
Yes, sir.
It will never hurt
anyone again.
Perhaps I should escort
the Doctor, sir.
Fine, but don't
leave her unattended.
Please come with me,
Doctor.
Of course.
I will stay
with you, Doctor.
How long will you live, Data?
There has been
no predetermined limit
placed on my existence,
Doctor.
I'm glad.
As long as you're alive,
he'll be alive.
I need your help, Data.
In what way, Doctor?
Like you did before.
Tell me...
that you understand,
Renny.
Yes.
That... that you know
I did it for you.
'Cause I love you.
Because I wanted to
give you peace at last.
I do not find such a file
in your son's journals,
Doctor.
However, from what
I know of him,
by his memories
and his writing,
I do not believe
he would be happy.
He was proud of your career
as a scientist,
and now you
have destroyed that.
You say
you did it for him,
but I do not believe
he would have wanted that.
Yes...
I believe your son
would be very sad now.
I am sorry, Doctor,
but I cannot help you.