Captain's Log,
Stardate 45156.1.
Our mission to Mudor Five
has been completed.
And since our next assignment
will not begin for several days
we're enjoying a welcome
respite from our duties.
If it's a boy, Michael,
after my father.
Wait a minute, we decided on
Hiro, after my father.
We talked about this
last night.
That's right, and we
decided on Hiro.
Wait. I've got it.
William. It's a great name--
William O'Brien.
It's got
a nice ring to it.
Oh... oh,
it's all right.
He's just doing
somersaults.
Here, feel.
Right there.
Oh. Going to be
a hell of a gymnast.
May I?
Sure. There.
Feel it?
When he's not turning,
he's kicking or punching.
When I want to sleep,
he wants to wake up.
At this point,
I just wish it were over.
I have to go.
I have a transporter
simulation on the bridge.
Bye-bye, Michael.
No.
Come on, Geordi.
Just try it once.
It is not as hard
as you think.
I'm telling you,
you will be terrific.
( sighs )
All right.
It's silly.
♪ I am the very model
of a modern major general ♪
♪ I've information vegetable,
animal and mineral... ♪
Nah, I can't--
I can't do this.
Yes, you can!
I cannot sing
in front of people!
You were terrific!
You were
a little off pitch
but I think
I can take care of that.
Okay, La Forge is
the Modern Major General.
Captain, I'd like
to introduce you to
the winners of
the primary school science fair.
This is Marissa,
Jay Gordon, and Patterson.
They're here
for their tour.
Hello.
Can we see the Battle
Bridge and Torpedo Bay?
No, I'm afraid not,
but we will be visiting
the hydroponics
and the astrophysics
laboratories.
I'm sure you'll have
a wonderful time.
Well... if you'll
come with me.
I'm not sure
who to feel sorry for--
the captain or the kids.
I want you to know that
we're very proud
of our science fair
winners.
Perhaps some of you will...
choose to pursue a career
in Starfleet.
Well, then, um...
What did you do
for your science projects?
I planted radishes
in this special dirt,
and they came up all weird.
I see. That's very...
very commendable.
And you?
An analysis
of the lifespan of the swarming
moths on Gonal Four.
They only live for 20 hours.
Then they all die.
How interesting.
And you?
( crashing )
( kids screaming )
PICARD: We're falling!
( people shrieking )
Uhh!
Agh!
( crashing )
( alarm blaring )
What happened?
Sensors are picking up
subspace distortions
and high-energy particles
directly to starboard.
Looks like we ran into
a quantum filament.
Damage report?
We've lost primary
life-support.
Switching
to secondary systems.
Impulse and warp engines
are off-line.
There's another filament
moving toward us, sir.
All decks brace for impact.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Counselor.
I'm all right.
Medical team
to the bridge.
Troi to sick bay.
TROI: Counselor Troi
to Captain Picard.
Troi to engineering.
Counselor Troi
to any crew member.
Please acknowledge.
Medical team
to the bridge.
The computer's down.
It looks like
we still have impulse power,
but not much else.
Lieutenant Monroe.
Chief O'Brien...
the turbolifts aren't working.
We're trapped up here.
( kids crying )
Are you...
are you children all right?...
Bridge, this is Picard.
This is the captain.
Does anyone read me?
(crying)
Why don't they answer?
I don't know.
They're all dead.
PICARD:
They're not dead.
Communications down, that's all.
We're going to die too.
We most certainly are not.
Now, listen to me.
No one here
is going to die.
The bridge will be sending a
rescue party as soon as possible
so I want you all
to stop crying!
Everything is going
to be all right!
( crying )
( kids sobbing )
This is the Federation
Starship Enterprise
calling any vessel
within range.
We are in distress,
and need assistance.
Please respond.
( static )
I'm still not sure
if we're transmitting.
I'll set the message
on auto-repeat
and see if we get a response.
You all right?
I'm alive, what the hell
happened?
We were hit
by a quantum filament.
Most of our systems
are down.
We haven't been able to contact
anybody off the bridge.
Well, don't count on leaving
through there.
An emergency bulkhead closed
just beneath that lift.
Confinement mode.
Right, isolation protocol.
I'm not really familiar
with that protocol.
If the computer
senses a hull breach
it automatically closes
emergency bulkheads
to isolate the breach.
Until we can clear
those bulkheads
we'll be cut off
from the rest of the ship.
MANDEL: I have partial sensors
back on line.
I'm picking up
sporadic life signs
throughout
the saucer section.
There are definitely
survivors.
What about ten forward?
Ten forward?
My wife's there.
I'm sorry, Chief.
The readings
are not that specific.
Can you scan
the drive section?
I'm not reading any
life signs in the drive section.
Could the sensors
be malfunctioning?
There's no way to know--
without the main computer
I can't run a full diagnostic.
Can you sense anything,
Counselor?
There are a lot
of people still alive.
Many of them are hurt,
but I can't tell
where they are.
We need to start
emergency procedures.
Who's the duty officer?
Lieutenant Monroe
was in command,
but she's dead.
I believe
counselor Troi
is the senior officer
on the deck.
Counselor Troi?
She carries the rank
of Lieutenant Commander.
I'd, uh...
I'd appreciate some suggestions.
I recommend we initiate
emergency procedure Alpha Two.
Bypass computer control,
and place
all systems
on manual override.
Very well.
Aye-aye, sir.
May I suggest that
our next priority be
to stabilize life-support
and to try to reestablish
internship communications.
Yes. Mr. Mandel, I'd like
you to assist Ensign Ro.
Yes, sir.
How are you feeling?
Okay. A little foggy.
Just lie still for a while.
We're going
to get you to sick bay
as soon as we can.
Okay.
Report.
I have surveyed
all the turbolifts
and service crawlways
on this deck.
Access to the bridge
has been completely severed
by emergency bulkheads.
Sick bay?
Heavy damage to section 23-A
has cut off access to sick bay.
I have ordered a security team
to bring casualties here
until further notice.
I think we should
assume the worst.
That everyone
on the bridge is dead.
There's no one
in control of this ship.
In that circumstance,
reestablishing control
of the ship should be
our top priority.
Agreed. Can we get
to engineering?
No, sir. The most direct
route is blocked.
But I believe we can use
the starboard service crawlway.
Okay--you and I will try
to get there.
Mr. Worf, this room is about
to fill up with wounded
in a few minutes,
and they're going
to need help.
I want you to stay
in charge here.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Over here.
Yes, sir.
Okay. Clear the power shunt.
COMPUTER: The shunt is cleared.
Right. And bypass
flow current, and...
The computer still won't
release the doors.
Can we force them open?
Yeah, we can try.
There's an emergency
hand actuator.
Geordi...
Yeah?
This wall is hot.
Where?
I'm all right.
But I think we've got
a new problem.
One of the energy conduits
must have ruptured
and ignited the polyduranide
inside the bulkhead.
That's a plasma fire.
It's putting out
a lot of radiation.
We can't stay here
much longer.
Yeah, but we've got a bigger
problem than that.
The quaratum in those
containers is used
in emergency thruster packs.
It's normally pretty
stable stuff,
but when you expose quaratum
to radiation
it has a way
of exploding.
The external power
is cut off.
We're going
to die.
Wh-What was that?
PICARD:
I don't know.
( sighs )
Your name is Marissa,
that right?
Well, Marissa, I need
a first officer to help me.
You're the oldest and so
that makes you my number one.
Number one?
That's what I always call
my first officer.
So...here.
There.
Now, number one, we need a crew
to help us get that hatch off.
Don't you think
that Jay here would make
an excellent science officer?
What do you say, Jay?
Will you join our crew?
It's Jay Gordon.
Of course.
Forgive me, Jay Gordon.
I accept.
Here.
There.
Can I be
an officer too?
Well, let me see.
Your science project
involved radishes,
did it not?
Yes, sir.
Then I shall appoint you
my executive officer
in charge of radishes.
There.
Right!
Then let's get to work.
13-65 Baker.
That should put us right
behind shuttlebay two.
That is correct, sir.
We have approximately 52 meters
remaining in this crawlway
before we can safely exit
into a main corridor...
( whooshing )
Coolant leak!
( quiet hissing )
We can withstand this
level of radiation
for another three or four hours
without any permanent damage.
We'll need a few days
of hyronalin treatments.
What are the radiation levels
in the quaratum?
They're at 83 rads
and rising at a rate of about
four rads per minute.
That stuff gets unstable
at about 350 rads.
I still haven't been
able to get any power
in this transporter.
The radiation level
is about 20% lower
at this end of the bay.
Let's move the containers
over to here.
That's a good idea.
It'll buy us some time.
You know, we're going
to have to do this by hand.
With all the radiation
floating around in here
we can't trust
the anti-grav units.
There, just before
the second time we were hit.
See the subspace distortion?
Yes.
How big is
a quantum filament?
Well, it could be
hundreds of meters long
but it has almost no mass
which makes it very
difficult to detect.
So it's like
a cosmic string.
No, that's a completely
different phenomenon.
How did you do that?
I diverted power
from the phaser array
and I dumped it into
the engineering control system.
You what?!
Engineering stations
on-line, counselor.
But that's a completely
improper procedure.
You can't just dump
that much raw energy
into a bridge
terminal without...
We're not going to get out of
this by playing it safe.
What is our
engine status, ensign?
We've got half impulse
power available.
But I'm getting some odd
readings from the warp drive.
I'm reading a spike
in the warp field array.
It looks like
a containment deviation.
Switch
to primary bypass.
Nothing.
Field strength's
at 40% and falling.
We've got a problem.
The quantum resonance of the
filament caused a polarity shift
in the anti-matter
containment field.
When the filament hit us,
the ship was momentarily charged
as if it had come in contact
with a live electrical wire.
That weakened
the containment field
surrounding
the anti-matter pods.
The field strength is
at 40% and it is still falling.
If it falls to 15%,
the field will collapse
and we'll have
a containment breach.
Which means?
Which means
the ship will explode.
Commander, the current cannot be
shut off from this relay box.
We can't just sit here.
If the energy flowing through
that arc were interrupted
by a non-conductive material,
it is likely
the circuit would be broken.
I don't see
anything in here
that'll handle
that much current.
Commander, much
of my body framework
is made up of tripolymers,
a non-conductive material.
Are you suggesting
we use your body?
Yes, sir.
Data, there's half a million
amps going through that arc.
Could your body handle
that much current?
The power surge would cause
a systems failure
in my internal processors
and melt my
primary power couplings.
However, there
is a chance that
the damage would
not be irreparable.
No.
Commander...
our options
are very limited.
First of all, android or not,
I wouldn't ask anyone
to take that kind of risk.
Second, if the computer
is not working in engineering
I'm going to need your help
to get control of the ship.
My positronic brain has several
layers of shielding to
protect me from power surges.
It would be possible for you
to remove my cranial unit
and take it with you.
Let me get this straight.
You want me
to take off your head?
Yes, sir.
Is something wrong, sir?
Well, Data...
Would you be all right?
My memory core and neural nets
are self-contained.
I would be fine, sir.
Well, like you said...
our options are limited.
Data!
Oh... Data.
Data.
A remarkable experience,
commander.
Are you all right?
Did the shielding work?
Apparently so, sir.
My neural nets
are fully operational.
You may begin by opening
the ventral access panel
located two centimeters
below my right ear.
(Jay Gordon)
Ah!
Can you climb up?
Yes, I think so.
Good.
Now look down
the sides of the lift.
Can you see
two big clamps?
Yes, I see them.
Can you see if those clamps
are attached to...
long beams inside
big grooves?
Yes.
But one of them
looks broken.
It's half out of the groove.
All right, come down.
All right.
Guh! Uhh!
Number one.
Those big clamps are
part of the emergency system.
If anything goes wrong
they're designed to hold
the turbolift in place.
But it would seem
that they're damaged.
Is that why
we keep shaking?
That's right.
Now, when they give way,
we shall fall,
so you've got to get
your crew out of here
before that happens.
Now there's a ladder
that runs along the wall
of the shaft.
You can climb up that until
you come to an open doorway.
( creaking )
Well...
what about you?
My ankle is broken.
I will just slow you down,
and you need to move quickly.
Now you are the leader,
and that's an order.
We have to climb
up the shaft.
I want to stay here
with you, Captain.
Patterson, you're an officer.
You have to obey orders.
I don't want to be
an officer anymore.
I want to stay here
with you.
If the captain stays
here, we won't make it.
We'll all die.
We don't have time to argue.
You must go now.
The crew has decided
to stick together.
We all go or we all stay.
All right, I'll try.
But I want you to know
this is mutiny.
Now, number one,
look at that control panel.
Now, the yellow control pad,
hit that once.
Now, the one below it,
hit it twice.
Now that should release
the panel underneath.
Yes, it did.
Now, you can
pull it away.
Okay.
Good.
Now that bundle of wires,
that's optical cabling.
See how much of that
you can pull out.
The levels
are still rising.
There must be some way
to put that fire out.
The energy's fed by the ship's
internal power grid.
And we can't get near that.
The only way to stop it
would be to eliminate
its oxygen supply.
Wait a minute.
Doctor, I've got an idea.
Now it's kind of wild,
but we just might be able
to kill two birds
with one stone.
Let's hear it.
Okay. We open
the external door.
That would depressurize
the cargo bay
and suck all of these
containers out into space.
At the same time,
the lack of oxygen should put
out the plasma fire.
What about us?
We just need to find
something in here to hold onto
while the air
is evacuating.
Then we close the door,
repressurize the bay.
What about this?
Yeah.
Yeah, that ought
to do it.
There,
that should do it.
There will be a sharp pain
as I set the bone.
Prepare yourself.
Agh! Ooh!
Good.
Good, you bore
that well.
Ohh.
WORF:
Keiko?
I'm all right...
I think.
Perhaps you
should lie down.
Ohh!
Ohh! Uhh!
I'm having contractions.
I believe
that is not uncommon
in the late months
of pregnancy.
No, I mean contractions.
I'm going into labor.
You cannot.
This is not
a good time, Keiko.
It's not open for debate.
Like it or not,
this baby is coming.
If the containment
field strength
continues to drop
at its present rate,
we still have
at least two hours
before it
becomes critical.
But you're ignoring the fact
that the power coupling
is also damaged.
If that coupling overheats,
the field strength could drop
a lot faster.
We could have a containment
breach in a matter of minutes.
What do you suggest?
We should separate
the saucer now
and put as much
distance as possible
between us
and the drive section.
Excuse me, sir,
but that's damn
cold-blooded.
What about
the people down there?
There's no evidence
that anyone is alive
in the drive section.
No evidence
they're dead, either.
If you were
trapped down there,
would you like us
to cut you loose
and just leave?
No, of course not.
But I also wouldn't
expect the Bridge crew
to risk the safety of the ship
and hundreds of lives
in a futile effort
to rescue me.
You said there was no way
to stabilize
the containment field
from the bridge.
Could it be done
from engineering?
Yes, but my readings
indicate there's no power there.
They don't even have monitors
to tell them there's a problem.
Could we divert energy
from the bridge
to those monitors?
Yes, sir.
I will say it again:
there is no reason to believe
that anyone is still alive
in engineering.
We're wasting time
even talking about this.
We have to separate
the ship now.
I believe there are still people
alive down there...
and I'm going to give them
every chance.
Assuming they're alive,
they'll be hoping
there's someone up here
who can help them,
so we'll help them.
Chief, divert the necessary
power to engineering.
Aye, sir.
I remind you, Counselor,
that power coupling
could overheat at any moment.
By not separating
the ship now,
you could be responsible
for all our deaths.
Thank you, Ensign.
Proceed.
I can't open this door.
We're going to have to climb up
to the next deck.
(sighs)
What if that one
doesn't open, either?
Then we'll never get out.
MARISSA:
Quiet! Both of you!
That's an order.
PICARD:
We're going up.
Ready?
Ready, sir!
( loud clatter )
The lift's falling.
Hang on!
( distant crash )
PICARD:
We're all right.
We're going to keep on climbing.
Just don't look down.
( crying )
What's wrong?!
He's scared.
We're right with you,
Patterson.
You're not going to fall.
Everything will be all right
if you just keep climbing.
( grunting )
What we need...
is a climbing song.
Marissa, is there a song
that you sing
at school?
Um... "The Laughing Vulcan
and His Dog"?
I'm afraid
I don't know that one.
I know!
"Frere Jacques."
That's a song I used to sing
when I was at school.
Patterson?
Do you know that one?
Good! Goes like this:
♪ Frere Jacques, frere Jacques ♪
♪ Dormez vous ♪
ALL: ♪ Sonnez les matines ♪
♪ Sonnez les matines ♪
♪ Ding, ding, dong,
ding, ding, dong ♪
Very good.
Now, keep singing.
ALL: ♪ Frere Jacques,
frere Jacques ♪
♪ Dormez vous,
dormez vous ♪
♪ Sonnez les matines,
sonnez les matines ♪
♪ Ding, ding, dong,
ding, ding, dong ♪
♪ Frere Jacques,
frere Jacques ♪
♪ Dormez vous, dormez vous ♪
♪ Sonnez les matines,
sonnez les matines ♪
♪ Ding, ding dong,
ding, ding, dong ♪
♪ Frere Jacques,
frere Jacques... ♪
WORF: Your contractions are
now only 30 seconds apart.
Oh! Ohh!
Dilation has gone
to seven centimeters
since the onset of labor.
That did not take long.
It's easy for you to say.
Ahh!
( panting )
You are doing very well.
I'm sure the child
will arrive soon.
Whew! Ahh.
Worf, has the baby turned?
Turned?
So the head is down.
Dr. Crusher told me
a few days ago that it hadn't.
She wasn't worried
because I still had
a month to go.
I am not certain.
Can't you tell?
Worf, have you ever
done this before...
delivered a baby?
Yes... no.
I took the Starfleet
emergency medical course.
In a computerized
simulation,
I assisted in delivery
of a human baby.
Sometimes it doesn't
go by the book, Worf.
( groaning )
I am sure
everything
will be fine.
Once the air is vented,
the first thing
you'll feel is an extreme
pressure on your lungs.
You have to resist
the temptation to exhale.
Next, our hands and feet
will get cold, then numb.
And some of the capillaries
on the exposed sections
of the skin may burst.
Sounds like fun.
We will have about 15 seconds
of useful consciousness,
then about ten seconds
of extreme disorientation,
then we pass out.
Okay. Once the air
is evacuated,
one of us is going to need
to get to that panel
to repressurize the bay.
We're ready.
Are you okay?
( inhaling and exhaling )
( panting )
( breathing heavily )
RO: The field strength
is down to 20%.
We cannot run the risk
of staying here any longer.
We're in no danger
till it drops below 15%.
We can afford to wait and see
if someone in engineering
notices those monitors.
Have you made preparations
to separate the saucer section?
Yes, sir. We're in stand-by mode
for docking latches...
Ensign, there's
a thermal inversion
in the power coupling!
Quick! Cross connect it
to the transfer coil.
That was close.
What happened?
Exactly what I said
might happen--
the power coupling
overheated
and the entire containment
field almost collapsed.
O'Brien's fixed it
temporarily,
but this could happen
again at any moment,
and next time we might not
be able to stop it.
You can't let wishful thinking
guide your decision, Counselor.
It's time to leave.
We will separate the ship
when I decide that it's time
and not before.
Is that clear, Ensign?
Yes. Perfectly.
Okay, try it.
Very good, Commander.
You have established
a connection.
I can now raise the door.
There's no power
on this entire deck,
and yet somehow
these monitors are working.
The power reaching
those monitors
has been diverted
from the bridge, sir.
But why?
Unless there's something
they want us...
something they need us to see.
Wait a minute. Data,
the containment field strength
is down to 18%--
can you stabilize it?
No, sir. I do not have access
to the containment field.
You will have to establish
a new link.
Locate the O.D.N.
conduit, sir.
Got it.
Yes, sir.
You must now change
the input matrix
of my secondary optical port
and then connect
the O.D.N. conduit.
That is not
the correct port, sir.
Sorry.
You must hurry,
Commander.
The containment field
has dropped to 16%.
I'm trying.
You need a bigger head.
The field continues
to drop, sir.
Collapse is imminent.
Try it now?
I have made
a connection, sir.
I am now stabilizing
the containment field.
O'BRIEN:
Sir, the field strength
is stabilizing.
18%...
20...
25...
I guess they got
our message.
I was wrong,
Counselor.
You could have
easily been right.
( strenuous breathing )
( grunting )
( gasping )
WORF:
Congratulations.
You are fully
dilated to 10cm.
You may now give birth.
Ohh! That's what
I've been doing.
Well, bearing down
is the next stage.
It should start
at full dilation.
Why has it not begun?
I don't know!
I don't think it's up to me.
It happens
when it happens!
My computer simulation
was not like this.
That delivery
was very orderly.
Well, I'm sorry!
Uhh! Uhh!
( groaning )
Did you feel an
uncontrollable urge to push?
( groans loudly )
Good.
You are bearing down.
Now you must push
with each contraction
and I must urge you gently
but firmly to push harder.
Push, Keiko.
Push hard.
Push. Push!
Push!
I am pushing!
The baby is emerging
head first.
One more contraction.
( straining )
Oh-kay. Agh!
That's good.
Push.
Hard!
( wails )
I have the baby.
Ohh!
(laughing)
Oh. Oh.
Now I will smack the child
to induce breathing.
( light smacking )
( baby crying )
I will cut
the umbilical cord.
Blanket.
I believe she looks
like Chief O'Brien.
( laughing )
Ohh.
You were wonderful, Worf.
I couldn't have done it
without you.
Hello.
( baby cooing )
( giggling )
Hello.
Captain's Log: Supplemental.
We are en route to Starbase 67
to undergo repairs.
Life aboard the Enterprise
is slowly returning to normal.
Now just wait here.
You just can't stay away
from the big chair, can you?
I don't think I'm
cut out to be Captain.
First Officer, maybe.
I understand there
aren't many qualifications.
Captain Picard to the bridge,
please.
Hello.
It's good to see you again.
What brings you
to the Bridge?
In appreciation
for the way you helped us
get out of the turbo shaft
and the way you helped us
not be scared,
we want to present to you
this commemorative plaque.
Give it to him.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
I made the back piece.
Oh, and a wonderful job
you did of it, too.
Well, later this afternoon
we're going to finish
the tour I promised you,
starting with
the Battle Bridge.
I'll see you at 1400 hours.
You have the Bridge,
number one.
RIKER AND MARISSA:
Aye, sir.