( woman giggling )
RIKER:
Etana?
I know you're back there.
Don't make me come after you.
Oh!
( laughing )
Give me that.
You don't need that.
Yes, I do.
I need that
communicator.
Ha-ha-ha.
Oh! Oh!
Commander Riker
to Enterprise.
I have a terrible problem
down here on Risa.
Give me that.
Go get it.
I don't believe
you did that.
Believe it.
( giggling )
Mmm.
What is this?
It's a game.
Everyone here's playing it.
It's fun.
Do I keep my eyes
open or closed?
Open.
What am I seeing?
ETANA:
The playing field.
Now what?
You see the disk
and the cone?
Yeah.
Concentrate.
Make the disk
go into the cone.
How do I do that?
Just let go.
Relax.
You'll do it.
What was that?
Your reward...
for clearing
the first level.
How far does
this game go?
As far as you
can take it.
Would you like to go
for level two?
Hmm?
( Etana chuckling )
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45208.2:
Commander Riker has rejoined
the Enterprise from Risa.
And we are on our way
to an uncharted area
called the Phoenix Cluster.
We are all anticipating
this historic first look
at the region.
It's starting to get busy
around here.
Five new science teams just
beamed in from the Zhukov.
The quarters
are filling up fast.
On top of everything,
there's been a change.
We've been given only two weeks
to complete the exploration.
Two weeks?
That's not enough time to
explore a region that size.
I thought we had
five weeks.
Commander, Starfleet has
added a diplomatic mission
to Oceanus IV.
Will, I'm leaving it
up to you to make sure
that all the science departments
have an equal chance
of completing
their research.
Could be quite
a juggling act.
Oh, and one piece
of good news:
we're to rendezvous with a
shuttle carrying Wesley Crusher.
He's on vacation
from the academy.
Wesley, good. We'll need
an extra hand around here.
Geordi, how are you coming
with the survey preparations?
I'm up to my neck in observation
schedules right now.
Our biggest hurdle
is sensor availability.
Yeah, especially since
two new exobiologists
and three stellar cartographers
have joined us from the Zhukov.
15 science teams, only two
weeks, and one long-range array
doesn't make for
a great combination.
What about
the lateral sensors?
They're booked solid
for planetary observation.
And the gamma ray scanner?
We're reprogramming them now--
Lefler, a moment of
your time, please.
You know Robin Lefler.
Of course.
Her work around here
has been so sensational,
I've decided to make her
a mission specialist.
Congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
All right, specialist,
what is our sensor status?
We're increasing
the available bandwidth
so more science teams
can use the sensors at once.
We figured out a way to do it
by multiplexing the array.
Can we have that done
before we arrive?
Yes, sir,
you can count on it.
Keep it up, Lefler.
Geordi, I brought
something back from Risa
that you have got to try.
I'd love to,
but I'm running
a full sensor recalibration
in about ten minutes.
Can it wait?
Of course.
I'll catch up with you later.
Mm-hmm.
Chocolate ice cream,
chocolate fudge
and chocolate chips.
You're not depressed,
are you?
I'm fine, Commander.
Would you like me
to leave you two alone?
No, you can join us.
No, thanks.
I don't like fudge.
Really?
I never met a chocolate
I didn't like.
Doesn't it taste good?
Mm, of course it does,
but it's not just
a matter of taste.
It's the whole experience.
First of all,
you have to spoon the fudge
around the rim,
leaving only the ice cream
in the middle.
Then you gently spoon
the ice cream
around the sides,
like you're sculpting it.
Relish every bite.
Make every one an event,
and then,
with the last spoonful,
close your eyes...
I had no idea
it was such a ritual.
Chocolate is
a serious thing.
I brought something
back from Risa.
Better than chocolate.
Oh?
What is it?
Just a game.
Chief O'Brien.
Welcome back, Wesley.
Congratulations
on little Molly.
Thank you.
Wait till you see her, she's
the spitting image of her dad.
So where is everybody?
Is my mom around?
The senior staff
is in a meeting.
You're supposed to go to
your mother's quarters.
Oh.
Do you think
it would be all right
if I dropped in
just to say hi?
I'll check.
Chief O'Brien
to Bridge.
WORF:
Bridge here.
Wesley Crusher
has arrived
and wants to know if he can
stop by the Observation Lounge
to say... hi.
WORF:
I suppose that is acceptable.
Thanks.
Surprise!
Mom!
Oh, welcome home.
Hi, Mom!
PICARD: Wesley!
Captain!
Quomodo tua latinitas est?
Praestat quam prius.
Ooh!
Oppido bonum.
Your Latin has improved.
You're looking
very handsome.
You really do that cadet
uniform justice, Wesley.
I bet you're driving
all the girls wild.
Wesley...
Tarvokian pound cake.
I made it myself.
Thanks, Worf!
Wesley, was our attempt
to make you
uncomfortable effective?
You bet it was.
For a second there, I thought
I was on the wrong ship.
( laughing )
( contrived laughter )
Did you find
our deception pleasing?
Yeah. It's fun
to be surprised.
Are you here to work,
or to play, Mr. Crusher?
Sir?
I know you're on vacation,
probably would like to sleep,
spend some time
on the Holodeck...
but if you so incline,
we could use your help
for the Phoenix
Cluster survey.
Sounds great, sir.
Excellent,
soon as you get settled,
come down to Engineering.
We'll get you started, huh?
Okay.
Aww.
So what kind of
game is this?
Come by my quarters
and I'll show it to you.
Have you found the academy
challenging, Wesley?
Yeah.
I thought after
being on the Enterprise
it would be a breeze,
but there's a lot more to learn
than just starship operations.
What was your
first year like?
Although I did extremely
well scholastically,
my lack of
human understanding
often created
social obstacles.
Like what?
I particularly remember the
phenomenon of practical jokes,
several of which
I fell victim to.
Tell me about it.
The first week
that I was there,
this guy named
Adam Martoni
reprogrammed the sonic shower
to cover me with mud.
It took me a while,
but I got him back
really good.
Good for you.
Thanks.
I also found social
gatherings difficult.
There was one event,
an academy tradition,
the Sadie Hawkins dance?
They still hold it
every year.
A notably awkward
experience.
I know what you mean.
I can't even dance.
Really?
Your mother
is quite an expert.
She recently taught me.
The Dancing Doctor?
Yeah, she tried
to teach me, too,
but I just don't have
the knack.
I would be happy
to teach you dancing.
I have programmed
a comprehensive
17-part course
with some interesting
holographic partners.
I'll let you know.
I'll modify
the planetary scanners.
Just make sure we have
enough data lines open
for the stellar physics.
No problem.
I'll compress the signal flow.
All right.
Why aren't these registering?
You might try
calibrating them manually.
Excuse me?
The detectors-- they tend
to get temperamental.
You can try
calibrating them by hand.
Oh.
Oh, you're kidding?
The computer has to do this.
No. Look.
The subroutine lets you
do it from the panel.
Law 17: when all else fails,
do it yourself.
It's working.
Thanks.
Sure.
Uh, by the way...
I'm Wesley.
Wesley Crusher.
I know.
Just back
from the academy.
That's right.
Robin Lefler.
Hi.
( beeping )
Your neutrinos
are drifting.
They're what?
( beeping stops )
Geordi,
a conflict has arisen
between the Planetary Evolution
team and the Stellar Physicists.
Each wishes to be the first to
use the thermal imaging array.
Well, tell them
to flip a coin.
We've got to work together
on this mission,
otherwise we're never
going to get it done.
A coin-- very good.
I will replicate one
immediately.
DR. CRUSHER:
Dr. Crusher to Data.
Data here.
DR. CRUSHER: Do you have
a minute to join me in Sick Bay?
I need your help
with something.
Yes, Doctor.
On my way.
You wanted to see me, Doctor?
Yes, Data.
I need to ask you
to do something for me.
I'm working on a new experiment
with bio-active silicon.
Would you reprogram
this tricorder
to these specifications?
Certainly.
I'm sorry to bother you with it,
but I need it done quickly.
It does not
bother me, Doctor.
In fact, I am happy...
Computer,
secure Sick Bay.
COMPUTER: All entries to
Sick Bay are secured.
Let's see, I have
Novakovich for anthropology
and Horne
for creative writing.
Walter Horne?
Is he still teaching?
Yeah, he is,
and he's good, too.
And you'll be pleased to know
I took your advice.
The first week that I was there,
I went and met Boothby.
Ohh... how is old Boothby?
I...
I hope he didn't tell you
a lot of stories about me.
He didn't remember you, sir.
At first.
I found an old
yearbook photo of you
and he remembered you
right away.
He said he's
very proud of you
that you're captain
of the Enterprise.
Is he still tending grounds?
Or have the years finally
caught up with him?
Not that I can tell.
He took me on a grand tour
of the place.
He showed me every single
blade of grass practically.
I had the very same tour.
Sir...
what do the initials
"A.F." stand for?
A.F.?
Boothby said he caught you
carving those initials
into his prized elm tree.
A.F...
Oh...
just an acquaintance of mine.
Wesley, if you meet someone
whose initials you might want
to carve into that elm tree,
don't let it interfere
with your studies.
I failed organic chemistry
because of A.F.
DR. CRUSHER:
Crusher to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Doctor.
DR. CRUSHER: I need you
in Sick Bay immediately.
On my way.
He came in complaining
of a servo malfunction,
but my scans
came out negative.
Then he just collapsed.
What have you found?
His bio-systems
and positronic functions
seem to check out.
His power cells
are active.
From what I can tell,
his higher functions are intact,
but the signals aren't
getting from his brain
to the rest of his body.
It's like a he's in a coma.
Data performs self-diagnostic
routines on a regular basis.
We should take a look at his
logs, they may reveal something.
I recommend going through
his quarters as well,
you never know what
we might find.
Agreed.
Continue the analysis.
Keep me informed.
Standard security sweep shows
nothing out of the ordinary.
Personal logs...
diagnostics,
duty logs--
they all look normal.
There's no evidence of anything
that could lead to Data's
shutdown.
Maybe we should
ask his cat.
I guess I'd better
get back to Sick Bay,
see if there's any change
in his condition.
Dr. Crusher's got everything
under control, Geordi.
If there's any change,
you'd be the first to know.
I guess so.
Looks to me like
you need a break.
Unwind a little.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
I've got just the thing.
Why don't you join me
in Ten Forward?
There's something
I'd like you to try.
WESLEY: Conduits 12 and 22
are still down for testing.
ROBIN: We can reroute
through junction 14-B.
You have a funny way
of looking
at conduit configuration,
but it works.
That's law 36: you got
to go with what works.
What are all these laws
that I keep hearing?
They're my
personal laws.
Every time I learn
something essential,
I make up a law about it
so I never forget.
How many do you have?
102, so far.
Looks like the starboard array
needs another sub-processor.
It will be online
in a few minutes.
I'm way ahead of you.
They said you were good.
Why do I get the feeling
that you already know me?
I have few friends
at the academy.
Your name's come up
a couple of times.
That's really some stunt
you pulled on Adam Martoni
in the physics lab.
I just want to know how you got
the anti-matter regulator
to spray chili sauce?
There is another side
to that story.
Is it true what they say
about your birthmark?
This isn't fair.
I hardly know
anything about you.
Hey...
that's law 46:
life isn't...
...always fair.
Yeah, I know that law.
I still have to work
on the sensor relays,
but I'd like a chance
to even the score.
Ten Forward,
1900 hours.
Will you join me
for coffee?
No.
But I'll meet you
for dinner.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
We have arrived
at the Phoenix Cluster,
but it will take us
several hours
to determine the best
possible location
from which to conduct
our survey.
Commander Data's condition
remains unchanged
with no further indication
as to the cause
of his collapse.
( gasps of pleasure )
Mom?
Wesley!
What are you doing?
I'm embarrassed to say.
This was meant for you,
but it was so much fun,
I couldn't resist.
What is it?
It's a game.
Riker brought it back
from Risa.
Everybody's playing it.
Want to try?
Maybe later.
How's Data?
Geordi is still
working on him.
He's going to be fine.
I think I should
go give him a hand.
No.
Wesley, you are on vacation.
You have done enough already.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Computer,
increase light level.
Are you in a hurry?
Yeah, I'm late
for a dinner date.
Really?
With who?
Robin Lefler,
from Engineering.
Why don't you
invite her here?
We can all play
the game together.
I can replicate
a couple more.
Mom...
Sorry.
It's just that...
I want to spend some time
together while you're here.
We'll have time together.
I promise.
Okay.
Just one game.
Come on, try it on...
Mom, I really need
to get ready.
Have a good time.
Thanks.
I will.
When your parents
are the only plasma
specialists in the sector,
you do a lot
of traveling around.
We went from base
to base to base.
I felt like a piece of
luggage after a while.
I spent all of my time
around technical equipment.
My first friend
was a tricorder.
Really?
My very first friend
was a warp coil.
My parents work
came first.
They didn't really
have time for me.
Even when I needed them.
So that's how I learned
my first law.
Law one: you can only
count on yourself.
Sounds kind of lonely.
Well, now you're here.
Now I'm here.
Well, I'm glad.
So you wouldn't believe
what's going on in Engineering.
Commander La Forge
and all the others,
they're crazy about
some new game.
Yeah, what kind of
game is it?
It's some Risian gadget
that fits over your ear.
Have you played it?
Mm-mm. Not yet.
My mom has one.
She keeps trying to get
me to play it.
It's everywhere.
See what I mean?
Don't you think that's
a little strange--
everybody playing it,
all the time?
It's just a fad.
It's here this week.
Next week, we won't
even know it existed.
I wonder how it works?
Why don't you try it
and find out?
I'd like to know a little bit
more about it before I try it.
I bet if we work together,
we could figure it out.
Yeah, we could hook it up
to one of the computers.
The medical programs
in the lab
can be set up to emulate
human responses.
I noticed it uses
a visual interface.
We could connect it through
an optical sensor.
I've loaded the neurological
behavior program.
This sensor pad will allow
the computer to process
whatever information
the game sends at it.
Let's see what happens.
Okay.
It's activating
the reticular formation.
There's heavy synaptic activity
all over the place.
I wonder what happens
after prolonged exposure.
Speed up the processor
and we'll find out.
ROBIN: The effects seem centered
around the frontal lobe.
Computer, enhance
frontal lobe, full spectrum.
ROBIN: It's stimulating
the septal area.
That's the pleasure center
of the brain.
Whatever this thing does,
it must feel pretty good.
No wonder
it's so popular.
Look at this.
Serotonin levels
are way off.
Let's run
a neurochemical analysis.
I'm seeing widespread bonding
to neuro-receptors.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but this looks like
a psychotropic reaction.
Are you saying you think
the game's addictive?
What's going on in
the prefrontal cortex?
ROBIN: Doesn't that area
control higher reasoning?
Yeah, it sure does.
I better go talk
to the Captain.
Come.
Sorry to bother you, sir.
It's no bother, Wesley.
Please, sit down.
Thanks.
How are the survey
preparations coming along?
They're coming along fine,
but that's not what I'm here
to talk to you about.
What then?
There's a game going around.
It's something that Commander
Riker brought back from Risa.
It's a device that hooks
around the ears.
Hmm.
Yes, I've seen it.
I did some preliminary
tests on the game.
And what I found
leads me to believe
that it may have some
harmful side effects.
Specifically, sir, I think
it's psychotropically addictive.
Addictive?
What have you discovered?
The game initiates
a serotonin cascade
in the frontal lobe
of the brain.
Now, I know that's
nothing conclusive,
but it could explain why
everyone is so attracted to it.
And at the same time,
it stimulates the brain's
reasoning center.
I don't know
what that's all about.
Hmm.
I'll start
an investigation immediately.
Thank you, Mr. Crusher.
Thank you, sir.
Wesley...
it's good to
have you back again.
O'BRIEN:
Have you tried this?
I've tried it.
Thanks, it's great.
Robin...
Where have you been?
Everybody's after me
to try it.
I know. I got stopped
in the corridors twice.
I talked to the Captain.
He's going to look into it.
Well, I hope he makes
a ship-wide announcement
or something.
Because this thing is really
starting to give me the creeps.
Did you forget your games?
We left them
in our quarters.
Well, then, you can use mine.
No, thanks.
Try it.
She said, "No, thanks."
You know what else
is really weird?
If this game is so addictive,
there's only one person on board
we can be sure wouldn't be
affected by it.
Data.
Right.
And he managed
to get injured
right when the game
was brought on board.
We better take
a look at him.
WESLEY: Maybe you should
go check again.
The nurse is still
playing the game.
I don't know what
to make of this.
There's brain activity, all
his systems seem to be working.
How can that be?
He's unconscious.
Maybe there's a signal breach
between his brain and his body.
Let's map his neuro-system
and see if we can
isolate a weak link.
Patch the neural output
through to that station.
Here!
The signal stops just below
his cortex processor.
There's some kind of damage.
It's almost unreadable.
Let's look at it
on the viewer.
Wesley, look at that.
It looks like some of
his positronic links
have been severed.
The cuts are precise.
Look at how clean
the edges are.
Computer, increase
magnification, factor four.
Only two people on board
know enough about Data
to do something like this--
Commander La Forge...
and my mother.
Why would one of them
do this to him?
Maybe there's more going on
here than we thought.
What if someone's trying
to use the game
for some purpose
other than pleasure?
Then Data would be
a threat to that plan,
and only with Data
out of the way
would everyone
become addicted.
And everyone has...
except us.
We have reached the designated
coordinates, Captain.
There's a ship bearing 327.152
on an intercept course.
Advise them of our status,
Mr. Worf.
Go, replicate what you need
and see that the devices
are properly distributed...
not forgetting
Mr. Crusher.
Wesley?
WESLEY:
In here, Mom.
( both panting )
It worked.
We should keep
these mock-ups with us.
We can't trust anyone anymore,
not even the Captain.
I'm supposed to be on duty
in Engineering.
I've got to go before Commander
La Forge suspects something.
Okay. When you get there,
start accessing the codes
to the security
tracking system.
There's something
I want to try.
Wesley,
don't forget law 91:
always watch your back.
You, too.
The vessel is approaching,
Captain.
Computer, all senior officers
report to the Bridge.
On screen.
Report.
PICARD:
Welcome, Etana.
The Enterprise
has been secured.
We await
your further instructions.
The expansion
will proceed as follows:
Commander Riker,
you will pilot a shuttlecraft
to the Cleon system
where you will rendezvous
with the starship Endeavor.
Proceed with distributing
the device to that vessel.
Commander La Forge,
Counselor Troi,
take a shuttle
to Starbase 67.
Distribute the device
to all starships
currently docked there.
We also have
an opportunity
to introduce the game
to Starfleet Academy.
Excellent.
See to it.
The Ktarians commend
your efforts, Picard.
Once the expansion
is complete,
you and your crew
will be rewarded.
( moaning )
Deck 36.
Wesley, and what
level are you?
I'm only level 10.
I'm at level 47.
( gasping )
That's great.
You know what
the secret is, don't you?
Don't force it.
If you just let
the game happen,
it almost
plays itself.
( gasps, sighs )
I'll try that.
I think we're
going to be okay.
I've just got
one more thing to do.
Help me compile
the force field overrides.
What are you doing?
I created a site-to-site
transporter program.
If things get difficult,
this will keep us one
step ahead of them.
Were you able to access
the security tracking codes?
Robin?
It's your turn.
Play the game,
Wesley.
RIKER:
Get back here!
Computer, activate
security containment field,
Deck 36, Section 52!
Computer, transport
program Crusher One.
RIKER: Riker to Bridge,
we lost Crusher.
It appears he rigged
a site-to-site transport.
Security alert,
condition three.
Computer, shut down
all Transporter systems
and Shuttle Bays.
Mr. La Forge?
I can't track him, sir.
He's done something to
the internal security sensors.
I'll try bypassing
his subcommands.
Hold on.
I'm picking up a piece
of his trail, sir.
Sensors show power activation
in Transporter Room Three.
That would put him
somewhere on Deck six.
Seal off Deck six.
Activate security fields
sections 23 through 29.
Aye, sir.
We've got him, Captain,
Section 25.
Looks like he's trying to
cut through the force field
with a phaser.
Security to Deck six,
Section 25...
SECURITY:
On our way.
RIKER:
Where the hell is he?
WORF: I am attempting to isolate
him with thermal sensors.
Narrow the scan field.
Go deck by deck if you have to.
Unfortunately,
he knows our procedures.
He will avoid all
corridors and public areas.
Commander,
an unidentified heat source.
Deck seven, Section 23.
There!
( grunting )
No!
Let go of me!
DR. CRUSHER:
It's okay, Wesley.
You led us quite
a chase, Mr. Crusher.
Dr. Crusher.
No!
Hold him steady.
DR. CRUSHER:
It's okay, Wesley.
It won't hurt.
No!
You'll like it.
His eyes.
DR. CRUSHER:
That's right, Wesley.
Just let it go.
Yes.
Just let yourself go.
Relax.
Computer, resume
normal illumination.
Mr. Worf, you will find
a small alien ship
off the starboard bow.
Please secure it with a tractor
beam and raise our shields.
Engaging tractor beam.
DATA: Are you all right,
Captain?
I think so, Mr. Data.
Captain, we are being hailed
by the alien vessel.
On screen.
Explain yourself, Picard.
The explanation is simple.
Your attempt to capture
our ship has failed.
Release us immediately
or we will open fire.
Tactical analysis,
Mr. Worf.
Their weapons systems are
substantially inferior to ours.
They are not a threat.
Get her off the screen.
I can't believe what
we were about to do.
Data, we deactivated you.
I managed to reconnect
his positronic matrix.
DATA:
Wesley's subsequent diversions
gave me adequate time
to modify the palm beacon.
The optical burst patterns
we programmed
were successful
in counteracting
the addictive effects
of the game.
And the rest of the crew?
We programmed
the main computer
to transmit the same
optical burst
to all display screens,
stations, and terminals
throughout the ship.
That should reach
almost everyone.
Take a medical team
to treat the rest.
Aye, sir.
We'll take the alien ship to
the nearest Federation Starbase.
Ensign, lay in a course.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45212.1:
We have delivered the Ktarian
vessel to Starbase 82
and are now on a course
to rendezvous
with the starship Merrimac,
which will transport
Wesley Crusher
back to Starfleet Academy.
I never saw you
wear these.
Afraid someone might
see your birthmark?
Now I wonder who started
that birthmark rumor.
I wish you
didn't have to go.
Me, too.
You'll write,
won't you?
Somebody has to kill
all those rumors
you keep hearing about me.
RIKER: Mr. Crusher, we've
rendezvoused with the Merrimac.
Please report
to Transporter Room Two.
On my way, sir.
I got to go.
Here.
A gift.
So you'll remember.
Robin's laws,
all 102 of them.
Thanks.
Law 103?
Yes?
A couple of light years
can't keep good friends apart.
Bye.