Captain's Log,
Stardate 45233.1.
Our terraforming mission
to Doraf One has been cancelled
and the Enterprise recalled
to Starbase 234.
Fleet Admiral Brackett
would not discuss the matter
on subspace for reasons
she said would soon be clear.
I apologize, Captain,
for the mystery,
but we must attempt
to contain the information
I'm about to reveal to you
at least as long as possible.
I must admit, you've piqued
my curiosity, Admiral.
Three weeks ago,
one of our most
celebrated ambassadors--
an advisor to
Federation leaders for
generations-- disappeared.
He left no word
of his destination.
Two days ago, intelligence
reports placed him on Romulus,
and I assure you, it was
an unauthorized visit.
Computer, initiate linkage
between this terminal
and Starbase computer
system Alpha 29.
Linkage complete.
A defection?
If it is, the damage
to Federation security
would be immeasurable.
Taken on Romulus
by long-range scanner.
Computer, enhance image
in section four Delta.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45236.4.
As I study
the intelligence reports
on Ambassador Spock's
disappearance,
I cannot help but feel
a deeper,
more personal concern
about this mission,
for I know this man
through his father.
It was barely a year ago
that I shared a mind meld
with the Vulcan Sarek.
Now we must meet again
as I attempt to find
an explanation
for his son's actions.
We're coming into orbit
of Vulcan in less than
an hour, Captain.
We should tell
Sarek's wife of our plans.
It's already been
taken care of.
She's transporting over
at 0700.
And Sarek?
She says he's too ill to
make the trip with her.
The man is dying, and it's
my honor to tell him
that his son may have
betrayed the Federation.
How well
do you know Spock?
I only met him once.
What I know of him
comes from history books
and, of course, my
mind meld with his father.
Well that must
cover a lot of ground.
Not as much
as you would imagine.
Sarek and Spock...
well...
sometimes fathers
and sons...
Understood.
Oh, one other thing.
Take a look at this.
Turned up during
an intelligence sweep.
Metal fragments.
What do you make of it?
Possibly, disassembled
components identified
as Vulcan
recovered from
a downed Ferengi vessel?
They were found in crates
marked "medical supplies."
Contraband?
It's been sent to Vulcan
for identification.
Starfleet have requested
that we lend a hand.
Mint tea. It's been years
since I've had any.
Vulcans have some kind
of strange concoction
they call mint.
You'd never recognize it.
Perrin, do you know why
I've come to Vulcan?
I must talk to you
about Spock.
He didn't even say good-bye
to his father before he left.
Is it possible he could
have been abducted?
No. He wrapped up all
of his affairs carefully.
He knew he was going.
Do you have any idea
why he might have
disappeared like this?
Captain,
as far as I'm concerned,
he disappeared
a long time ago.
Would it
be inappropriate
to ask what happened
between you and Spock?
Not between us.
Between Spock
and his father.
Oh, they had argued for
years, that was family,
but when the debates over
the Cardassian War began,
he attacked Sarek's
position publicly.
He showed no loyalty
for his father.
I was not aware that
Sarek was offended
by Spock's opposition.
I was offended.
I made sure
that Spock knew it.
I'm very protective
of my husband.
I do not apologize
for it.
Does Sarek have any idea
why Spock might have left?
I don't know.
If you could see Sarek
as I do--
wasting in bed,
whispering to himself...
He wants to see his son.
He wants to heal any rift
that may still remain.
Now it may be too late.
Perrin...
would you allow me
to see Sarek?
If it were anyone else,
I would never permit it,
but you are a part of him
and he of you.
The Vulcans
haven't figured out
what these fragments are,
but they've determined
that the metal
is a dentarium alloy.
Well, that pretty well
indicates that they're Vulcan.
Dentarium also means
that whatever this was,
it was originally designed
for use in space.
From the look of the
damage, it must have been
a high-speed impact.
Yeah, a Ferengi cargo
ship that went down the
Hanolin asteroid belt.
The debris was spread
over 100 square kilometers.
Could it be
a weapons array?
That was my first thought,
but the Vulcans
have no record
of any stolen weapons
or stolen parts,
for that matter.
This is going to be
like putting together
a big jigsaw puzzle
when you don't even
know what the picture
is supposed to be.
Yep.
( grunting and moaning )
He is like this
most of the time.
His emotions
have taken over.
Sometimes I can
bring him out of it.
Sarek!
You will listen.
Go from me.
Picard is here.
No more chaos.
No more.
I will leave you
alone with him.
He will either acknowledge
you or he won't.
Sarek...
I've come a long way
to see you.
I will not answer.
I must talk to you
about your son.
I wish no one with me.
About Spock.
Spock?
Yes.
He's missing.
Is that you?
Picard?
Hello, old friend.
You are here, on Vulcan.
I need your help.
I must find Spock.
He's not here.
I know.
He's been reported
on Romulus.
Romulus?
Yes.
Why?
I had hoped to find
that out from you.
On Romulus?
You're going there,
aren't you?
To find him.
Yes.
Do you have any idea
what might have taken
him to Romulus?
No.
Is there anyone
on Romulus he might know
or choose to contact?
Pardek?
Who is Pardek?
It could be Pardek.
He is a Romulan senator.
Spock has maintained
a relationship with him
over the years.
I don't know how they met.
At the Khitomer conference,
I'd imagine.
Pardek represented Romulus?
Yes.
I'm sure he did.
In fact, I recall
Spock coming to me
with optimism
about maintaining
a continual dialogue
with the Romulans.
I told him that it was
illogical to maintain
such an expectation.
Spock was always
so impressionable.
This Romulan Pardek
had no support at home.
Of course, in the end,
I was proven correct.
I gave Spock the benefit
of experience, of logic.
He never listened.
It has been suggested that
Spock might have defected.
Never.
I will accept many things,
but never that.
But you believe
he might have gone
there to see Pardek?
The Romulan senator?
How do you know Pardek?
I've heard of him.
That's what he's done.
He's gone to see Pardek.
Do you know what business
they might have together?
No. I never knew
what Spock was doing.
When he was a boy,
he would disappear for
days into the mountains.
I would ask him where he
had gone, what he had done.
He refused to tell me.
I insisted that he tell me.
He would not.
I forbade him to go.
He ignored me.
I punished him.
He endured it silently.
But always, he returned
to the mountains.
One might as well ask
the river not to run.
But secretly,
I admired him--
the proud core of him
that would not yield.
Sarek, we're a part
of each other.
I know that he
has caused you pain,
but I also know
that you love him.
Tell him, Picard...
Peace and long life.
Live long and...
and...
( sobbing )
Spock...
my son...
And prosper.
Captain's Log:
Stardate 45240.1.
To cross the neutral zone,
I will require a cloaked ship.
To that end, I have
set a course for the
Klingon home world.
After all we did for Gowron
during the recent war,
I'm certain he will be
happy to return a favor.
Still no response from
the Klingons, Mr. Worf?
No, sir.
He's ignoring me.
What other
explanation is there?
It seems after hailing him
for three days,
he could have found
a minute to talk to you.
Sir.
Yes, lieutenant?
I believe I know
why our messages are
not being answered.
Gowron has been rewriting
Klingon history.
Rewriting history?
Yes. He is claiming
that it was his courage,
his genius that brought
an end to the civil war.
I see.
In the new version,
there is no mention made
of the Federation's help
in his rise to power.
If Worf's right, then
our arrival will be
an uncomfortable
reminder of the facts.
Well, he can take all
the credit he wants.
I don't care,
but I do need a ship.
Well, if Gowron won't
talk to me, get me
somebody who will--
somebody on the high
council-- K'tal perhaps.
Yes, sir.
Captain, I have a
visual identification
of Senator Pardek
of Romulus.
This is a Barolian record
of a trade negotiation
in which Pardek participated
four years ago.
That's all?
Yes, sir.
Run it again.
PICARD:
Computer, freeze.
Call up the intelligence
scan of Spock on Romulus.
PICARD:
Computer, enhance
far left figure and compare.
Same man-- Pardek.
One question answered.
What do we know of him?
He has been in
public service since
he was a young man.
A senator
for nine decades.
He is considered
a man of the people.
He has sponsored
many reforms.
Reportedly, Romulan
leadership considers him
to be somewhat of a radical
because he has been
an advocate of peace
throughout his career.
I can see why Spock
would cultivate
a relationship with him.
Where would we find him
other than on the floor
of the Romulan Senate?
The district he
represents is called
the Krocton segment.
He maintains
a dwelling there.
Thank you, Mr. Data.
There is more, sir.
I have taken the liberty
of expanding the
parameters of my search
and have discovered that
Pardek has several relatives
in the Krocton segment.
I believe you will be able
to locate him there
on the third day
of the Romulan week
when the senate
is not in session.
Mr. Data, your resourcefulness
never ceases to amaze me.
Thank you, sir.
Captain, we are being hailed
by the Klingon home world.
Gowron or K'tal?
Neither, sir.
It is the junior adjutant
to the diplomatic delegation.
Junior adjutant?
Name.
B'ijik, sir.
On screen.
Greetings, Captain.
I regret to inform you that
Gowron and the high council
are quite busy and
won't be able to
speak with you today.
Is Gowron aware that we have
been transmitting messages
for the past three days?
Captain, Gowron wishes
it were possible
to talk with everyone
who wants an audience,
but he is one man--
the demands on his time
are formidable.
If you would like me
to take him a message...
A message?!
Very well.
Tell Gowron,
leader of the high council
of the Klingon empire,
that his arbiter
of succession,
Jean-Luc Picard,
needs... a favor.
A favor?
I require a cloaked vessel.
A cloaked vessel?
This is no small
favor, Captain.
It is for a mission
that could have
repercussions
throughout the quadrant.
How would it benefit
the Klingon empire?
I'm sure Gowron will ask.
The only benefit
to the Klingon empire
would be our gratitude.
That is what you want me
to tell him?
Yes, and please add
that if he is unable
to provide us with a ship,
then I am sure there are
others in the Klingon empire
who would be
willing to help me,
and then... they would
have our gratitude.
I see.
Also, please tell Gowron
that I am immensely gratified
that he is prospering
so well.
A tribute
to his skilled leadership.
They're not removable,
are they, Data?
Removable?
Your ears.
No, Doctor, they are
fully integrated components.
We'll have to do some molds
of his ears as well.
What about
his skin color?
We'll have to do some tests
on his skin pigmentation.
Changing it to appear Romulan
shouldn't be too difficult.
We just have to make sure
we can change it back
again afterwards.
Your right eye is
.004 higher than your left.
Nobody's perfect,
Doctor, but...
If you want a proper fit
to your prosthetic,
trust your tailor.
Anything from Gowron?
No, sir, but if, when you're
done with your "tailor,"
you'd join me in the cargo bay,
Mr. La Forge has made
some progress
with the metal fragments.
These two still have an
appointment with Mr. Mott
to have their
hairpieces designed.
30 minutes, Number One.
LA FORGE:
What we have here is a
navigational deflector array
or at least
what's left of one.
Who would want
a Vulcan deflector?
Beats me, Commander.
Every question we answer here
seems to bring up two more.
You're certain
this is Vulcan?
Yes, sir. Metallurgical
analysis confirmed that
and by running a
molecular pattern trace,
we were actually
able to identify
the ship as the T'pau.
It was decommissioned
years ago
and sent to the surplus
depot at Qualor Two.
As far as anybody knows,
it's still there.
Worf to Captain Picard.
Yes, Lieutenant?
A Klingon vessel
is decloaking
off our port bow,
compliments of Gowron.
Mr. Worf, will you convey
my gratitude to the captain
and advise him
that Mr. Data and I
will be transporting
over shortly?
Aye, sir.
I'd like to take
the Enterprise
to Qualor Two, sir.
See what's out there.
Agreed.
Thank you,
Mr. La Forge.
I know my duty,
Captain.
When I am given orders,
I follow them,
but I do
not like secrets.
I want to know why we
are going on this mission.
I'm sorry.
It's a classified matter.
You're going after
the defector, aren't you?
Defector?
Do you think information
like that stays a secret?
Ambassador Spock
has gone to Romulus
and you're
going after him.
Captain, your orders
are to take us
to a set of coordinates
near Romulus
and to bring us back,
and that is all
I'm prepared to discuss.
If we are discovered
by the Romulans,
it means death
for us all.
I realize that.
Hechu' ghos!
Very well, Captain,
we have set a course
for Romulus.
It may not be
what you're used to
on a starfleet ship.
Quite nice.
Thank you.
Captain K'vada, is this
the captain's quarters
or my own?
Both. We have
limited space.
We are a military ship,
not a pleasure craft.
Of course.
This will be fine.
You will sleep
Klingon-style.
We do not soften
our bodies by...
putting down a pad.
Good.
I prefer it that way.
You will take
your meals with us,
but we do not serve
Federation food.
Ah! I've been looking
forward to gagh.
Haven't had it for
quite a while, very fresh.
Meh hod.
Jatlh!
Mehmah ghos.
So'wl'chu.
Well, Captain, we
are at the border
of the neutral zone.
You mean to do this,
do you?
Yes, I do.
Un'ta.
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 45240.6.
The Enterprise is nearing
Qualor Two,
home of a Federation
surplus depot operated
by the Zakdorn.
We hope to find out how
the salvaged deflector array
ended up in the hands
of the Ferengi.
I have made contact,
Commander.
On screen.
I'm Commander William
Riker from the Federation
starship Enterprise.
Klim Dokachin.
Quartermaster,
surplus depot zed-one-five.
I need some information
about a Vulcan ship--
the T'pau.
It was sent
a few years ago.
Did you arrange
an appointment?
An appointment?
No.
Then I will be
unable to help you.
You may communicate
with scheduling.
Who does he think he is?
The quartermaster of
the supply yard with
information you need.
Right. Mr. Worf...
reestablish communication.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Dokaychin...
Dok-ah-chin.
Klim Dokachin.
Mr. Dokachin,
the information I need
involves a matter of major
importance to the Federation.
I'll need access
to your logs, your files.
My people
can do the work.
I don't allow outsiders
into my computer system.
All right. One of your
people can do the work.
I wish I had the people
to spare. I don't.
Well, sir,
what would you suggest?
I don't know. Contact me
when you reach orbit.
I don't believe this.
He's king of his
particular hill,
Commander.
You'll have to treat
him that way.
Counselor, this feels
like a perfect job for you.
Thank you for coming
on board, Mr. Dokachin.
Quite a ship you have.
We're tied into
your computers,
if you'd like
to access the files.
I don't usually see them
in such good condition.
By the time they get
to me, they're always
falling apart.
Mr. Dokachin,
we must find this ship,
and you're the only
one who can help us.
Who are you?
Deanna Troi,
ship's counselor.
He probably figures
that we don't get to see
a lot of handsome women
out this way,
and someone like you
might get a little more
cooperation from me.
He's probably right.
What was the name
of that ship, the T'pau?
The T'pau...
Vulcan registry...
There. Logged in,
stardate 41344.
Where's the ship now?
Docked.
Section 18, Gamma 12.
You want me
to take you there?
I'd appreciate it.
Helmsman,
lay in a heading
141 by 208,
ahead slow, 200 kph.
I suppose this is
your first visit to
a junkyard, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
You'd be surprised
at some of the things
I find on board
these ships.
I once found
a 14-foot Caldorian eel
on board a freighter,
in someone's locker.
Are you serious?
If you have time,
I'll show it to you.
I still have it.
Nursed her back to health.
We are approaching
the designated
coordinates, Commander.
On screen.
DOKACHIN:
What? Where is it?
What happened to it?
These are
the correct coordinates.
The T'pau is missing?
The T'pau... is missing.
How could a ship disappear
from your depot?
I'm not accustomed to
losing things, Commander.
I will find
your ship for you.
I have the T'pau
cross-referenced
in four different
directories.
When it was brought here,
was it stripped
of material, armament,
sensors?
Of course.
Well, can you tell us
what happened to its
navigational deflector?
It was routed to the
Tripoli, a holding vessel
on the outer rim
of the shipyard.
Well, it's not there
anymore. What's left
of that deflector
is laid out on the
floor of our cargo bay.
How can that be?
Perhaps we should pay
a visit to the Tripoli.
In all the time
that the Zakdorn
have operated this depot,
nothing has ever
been lost.
Never.
Approaching the coordinates
of the Tripoli, sir.
On screen.
DOKACHIN:
I do not understand this.
This is not possible.
We beam goods to the Tripoli
on a regular schedule.
There was
a shipment yesterday.
Another one
is set for today.
It must be there.
When is today's transport?
Just over two hours
from now.
A shipment of deuterium
storage tanks.
Ensign, align the Enterprise
so we appear to be one
of the abandoned ships.
Mr. La Forge,
when we're in position,
shut down the engines
and all systems except
sensors and life support.
Aye, sir.
I have a feeling someone's
going to be there to receive
those storage tanks.
I'll be very interested
to know who that is.
These quarters
were obviously intended
for one crewman, sir.
There is but a
single sleeping space.
I'm sure the Klingons
found it amusing to
put us in here together.
Since I do not require
sleep, I propose you
take the... shelf, sir.
I am content to stand.
Very well, Mr. Data.
Thank you.
Are you comfortable,
sir?
I suppose so.
Good night, Captain.
Sleep well, sir.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Sir?
Was I making noise, sir?
No, not exactly.
I was processing
all of the information
we have accumulated
on Romulan society.
I am preparing for the task
of impersonating a Romulan.
I see.
Would you like me
to discontinue, sir?
No, no.
Please go on.
What are you looking at?
I am not looking
at anything, sir.
I am continuing
to organize my files.
But you were looking at me.
I am sorry if I
was disturbing you, sir.
I will not look
in your direction.
Do you not wish
to sleep, sir?
I don't think so,
Mr. Data.
Let's go on
with the files.
I would be happy to.
I have been studying
the Krocton segment
as you asked
and have chosen the proper
site for our transport...
Captain K'vada to Picard.
Please come to the bridge.
Captain...
we've monitored
a subspace message
that might interest you.
Sarek is dead.
Commander, sensors
detect a ship approaching
at warp speed.
Identification?
Negative.
No transponder signal.
No subspace marker.
Sounds like they don't
want to be identified.
The ship is coming
out of warp, sir.
On screen.
LA FORGE:
Sensors indicate
a combat vessel.
Origin undetermined.
Heavily armed.
Mass and density
suggest that it's fully
loaded with cargo.
I'd say from these
internal scans
that a good deal of
that cargo is weaponry.
The ship is entering
at sector 12-delta-four.
He's taking the position
assigned to the Tripoli.
The coordinates
are identical.
Commander, readings
indicate surface-to-ship
transport has begun.
Mr. La Forge, bring
the engines back on-line
and restore all systems
to normal.
Aye, sir.
He's powering up engines,
turning to starboard.
Open a channel.
Open.
This is Commander
William Riker of the
U.S.S. Enterprise.
Identify yourself.
I repeat-- you have entered
a Federation depot--
identify yourself.
Sir, the ship
is locking phasers.
Shields up.
Red alert.
That ship easily matches
our armament, Commander.
He's coming about.
If you do not respond
to our hails,
we will take that as
evidence of hostile action.
There's an energy build-up
in their phaser banks.
Sir, they're
activating weapons.
Forward shields
down to 72%.
Boost power the shields.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, lock on to
their weapon systems only
and prepare to fire.
Forward shields down to 68%,
aft shields 40%.
On my mark, a .75 burst.
We just want to get
their attention.
Ready, sir.
Fire.
Their forward shields
are damaged, sir.
We destroyed one
of their phaser arrays.
Looks like collateral
damage in the cargo area.
Commander, I'm picking up
massive power fluctuations,
internal explosions.
With all the armament
that ship is carrying,
it's going to blow.
PICARD:
Well, Mr. Data,
what do you think?
I would not have thought
it possible, sir.
I am eager to test the
success of our efforts.
It does remain to be seen
whether the Romulans
will accept us.
Captain, you've seemed
unusually pensive
since we received the news
of Ambassador Sarek's death.
Sarek and I share
a particular bond.
Our lives touched
in an unusual way.
I admit, I feel
the effects of his death.
The tenor of this mission
has changed, Mr. Data.
At least, it has for me.
We were sent to confront Spock
about his disappearance
and now I also have to tell
him that his father is dead.
I do not entirely
understand, sir.
As a Vulcan, Ambassador Spock
would simply see death
as the logical result
of his father's illness.
It's never quite that simple,
not even for a Vulcan.
Certainly not for Spock,
who is half human.
Years spent in conflict,
and now the chance
to resolve those
differences is gone.
Considering the
exceptionally long
lifespan of Vulcans,
it does seem odd
that Sarek and Spock
did not choose to
resolve those differences
in the time allowed.
Father and son--
both proud, both stubborn,
more alike than either of
them were prepared to admit.
A lifetime spent building
emotional barriers.
They are very difficult
to break down,
and now the time has come
and it's too late.
It's a difficult moment.
It's a lonely one.
It's a moment that
Spock is about to face.
( laughing )
Don't you two look sweet?
Be careful, android.
Some Romulan beauty
might take a liking to you.
( hisses )
Lick that paint
right off your ears.
You!
Do you know what the
Romulans will do to you
if they discover
who you are?
I have a good idea.
We're ready to transport
down to the surface.
Just so we understand
each other,
my orders don't include
rescue missions!
Ah, Senator Pardek.
You received my message.
I got here as quickly
as I could, pro-consul.
What do you know
of this human--
Jean-Luc Picard,
a starfleet captain?
I know nothing of him.
Then you haven't
seen him recently?
To my knowledge,
I have never seen him.
I have received
intelligence
indicating he
is on his way here,
perhaps here already.
Here on Romulus?
Yes.
Curious, isn't it?
I suppose
we'd better find out
if the report is accurate
or merely rumor.
Circulate his likeness
among the security forces.
Remind them
that if he is here,
he's probably disguised
as one of us.
I'll see to it.
This is definitely
the street on which
the intelligence scan
of Spock and Pardek
was taken, sir.
Adjusting for
the optical distortions,
I am able to verify
the architectural features.
Where were they standing?
Data, you're moving
about in a very...
well... android way.
I am sorry, Captain.
I will be more careful.
Don't call me Captain.
I understand, sir.
I have found the place
where they were standing.
Where?
It is here...
at this doorway...
a legal
intercessor's office.
The name is similar
to Pardek's.
It would appear to be
one of his relatives.
( knocking )
Not open
for business yet.
Nonetheless, I recommend
we keep this location
under observation.
I have clearly determined
Pardek's routine.
On days when the senate
is not in session,
he invariably comes
to this section
after the median hour.
Very well.
Let's, uh, sample the local
cuisine, shall we?
Do you happen
to know what time
the intercessor's office
across the way opens?
Why do you
want to know?
I need his services.
He was recommended.
I haven't seen you
here before.
We're here for the day
from the city of Rateg.
Rateg?
I don't think so.
Why do you say that?
You don't sound
like you're from Rateg.
It is a misconception
that all Rategs speak
with a particular
inflection.
In fact there are
12 different...
We come from several
kilometers outside the city.
Or perhaps you come
from the security forces
to watch the
intercessor's office.
Is he in trouble?
You're mistaken,
madam.
Doesn't matter to me.
I don't know
when he opens.
Eat your soup, courtesy
of a loyal establishment.
Jolan true.
I don't think we can
stay here too long.
We may not have to.
Direct your view
to the far corner, sir.
Is that not Pardek?
I believe it is.
Perhaps you should appear
to enjoy your soup, sir.
Do not move.
What?
Hey, you've made
a mistake.
Quiet. Come with us.
Wait here.
What for?
What have you
brought us here for?
Welcome to Romulus,
Captain Picard.
Don't let our
soldiers frighten you.
We had to get you
off the street as
quickly as we could.
Romulan security
knows that you're here.
I am Pardek.
You are among friends,
Captain.
I have come on
an urgent mission
from the Federation.
I'm looking
for Ambassador Spock.
MAN:
Indeed.
You have found him,
Captain Picard.