WOMAN:
Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
Three weeks ago, one of our
most celebrated ambassadors,
an advisor to Federation leaders
for generations, disappeared.
I gave Spock the benefit
of experience, of logic.
He never listened.
It's been suggested
that he might have defected.
Why would anyone want
a Vulcan shield array?
Beats me, Commander.
Every question we answer here
seems to brings up two more.
Be careful, android.
Some Romulan beauty
might take a liking to you--
lick that paint
right off your ears.
You, do you know what
the Romulans will do to you
if they discover
who you are?
I have a good idea.
Sir, the ship
is locking phasers.
Shields up.
Red alert.
What do you know of this human--
Jean-Luc Picard,
a Starfleet Captain?
You've made a mistake.
Quiet. Come with us.
I have come on an urgent mission
from the Federation.
I'm looking
for Ambassador Spock.
You have found him,
Captain Picard.
WOMAN:
And now the conclusion.
SPOCK:
What are you
doing on Romulus?
That was to have been
my question of you, sir.
It is no concern
of Starfleet.
On the contrary, it is very much
Starfleet's concern.
You are in a position
to compromise
the security of the Federation.
You may assure your
superiors, Captain,
that I am here on a
personal mission of peace.
And I will advise Starfleet
when it is appropriate.
That is not satisfactory.
You cannot remain here,
Captain Picard.
And I will not return
without a full explanation.
Ambassador,
with great respect
for all that you've achieved
on behalf of
the Federation,
this sort of cowboy diplomacy
will not easily
be tolerated anymore.
"Cowboy diplomacy"?
If you wish
to undertake a mission
with obvious repercussions
for the Federation
then you should discuss it
with the Federation.
I'm here
as their representative.
You'll have to discuss
it with me.
That is precisely what
I had hoped to avoid.
I also have
the responsibility
of being the bearer
of unhappy news.
Sarek?
Sarek is dead.
Walk with me, Picard.
I know of your mind meld
with my father
which enabled him
to complete his last mission.
It was an honor.
He's a great man.
He was a great representative
of the Vulcan people
and of the Federation.
I was with him
before coming here.
He expressed
his pride in you--
his love.
Emotional disarray
was a symptom
of the illness
from which he suffered.
No, those feelings
came from his heart.
He shared them with me.
I know.
Sarek would no more approve
my coming here
than you do, Picard.
For some time now
I've been aware of a growing
movement here of people
who seek to learn the ideals
of the Vulcan philosophy.
They have been declared
enemies of the state
but there are a few
in the Romulan hierarchy
like Pardek,
who are sympathetic.
He asked me to come now
because he believes it may be
time to take the first step
toward reunification.
Reunification?
After so many centuries?
After so many
fundamental differences
have evolved
between your peoples?
It would seem
unlikely to succeed
but I cannot ignore
the potential rewards
that a union between
our two worlds would bring.
What is this first step
that Pardek suggests?
There is a new proconsul
in the Romulan senate.
He is young and idealistic.
He has promised many reforms.
Pardek believes
that he may be receptive
to discussing reunification.
Why would you not bring
something so important
to the attention
of your own people
or the Federation?
A personal decision, Captain.
Perhaps you're aware
of the small role I played
in the overture to peace
with the Klingons.
History is aware
of the role you
played, Ambassador.
Not entirely.
It was I
who committed Captain Kirk
to that peace mission
and I who had
to bear the responsibility
for the consequences
to him and to his crew.
Quite simply, I am unwilling to
risk anyone's life but my own
on this occasion
so I ask that you
respect my wishes
and leave.
Ambassador,
your logic escapes me.
If I didn't know better,
I would say that
your judgment is influenced
by your emotions.
You speak as my father would
if he were here, Picard.
I speak as a Starfleet officer
and I cannot ignore
the risks to you.
I was involved
with "cowboy diplomacy"
as you describe it,
long before you were born.
Nevertheless, sir,
I'm not prepared to leave
until your affairs
are completed.
In your own way,
you are as stubborn
as another Captain
of the Enterprise I once knew.
Then I'm in good company, sir.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
We have more important
things to attend to
than acting
as your nursemaids!
Captain Picard
regrets detaining you
but it will be necessary
for a while longer.
In addition,
I require access
to your ship's computer.
Access to our computer?
For what purpose?
I am going to attempt
to penetrate
the Romulan central
information net.
Don't bother.
We've been trying for years.
I have unique skills
that may allow me to succeed.
I cannot reveal classified
Klingon entry codes
to Starfleet.
Your entry codes can easily be
reconfigured after we depart
and Captain Picard has
authorized me to share with you
any information we obtain
from the Romulan data banks.
Mmm.
K'VADA:
Anything else?
We will also need to communicate
with the Enterprise
in sector 2-13.
You do and the Romulans will
instantly know our coordinates.
Using conventional means,
that would be true.
However, I suggest we
piggyback our signal
on Romulan
subspace transmission.
Piggyback?
A human metaphor--
pardon me.
We would use a Romulan signal
as a carrier for our own
thus disguising its origin.
It won't work.
I believe it would.
During the last hour
I have conducted
a systematic review
of the entire Romulan
subspace grid.
I have compared my findings
with the specifications
of your own transmission array.
They appear
to be compatible.
Ja.
Thank you
for your cooperation.
♪♪
Allow me
to brighten your table.
Jolan true.
The senate has adjourned.
Pardek will be here shortly.
How widespread
is this movement?
There are groups
in every populated area.
I've personally spoken
to members from four provinces.
It has become a serious concern
for the Romulan leadership.
Serious enough for the leaders
to suddenly embrace
a Vulcan peace initiative?
I...
I have...
I have some difficulty
in accepting that.
I sense you have
a closed mind, Captain.
Closed minds have kept these
two worlds apart for centuries.
In the Federation
we have learned from experience
to view the Romulans
with distrust.
We can either choose to live
with that enmity
or seek a way to change it.
I choose the latter.
I will be the first to cheer
when the Neutral Zone
is abolished
but I wonder if this movement
is strong enough
to reshape the entire Romulan
political landscape.
One can begin
to reshape the landscape
with a single flower, Captain.
Jolan true, Mr. Spock.
Here.
Look what I've brought you.
This is my friend D'tan.
He's very curious
about Vulcan.
Hello, D'tan.
Where did you get this?
This is very old.
They read to us from it
at the meetings.
It tells the story
of the Vulcan separation.
D'tan.
You should not bring
that out here.
You've been told
many times.
I just wanted
to show it to Mr. Spock.
Off with you.
We'll see you
later tonight.
Will you tell us
more stories about Vulcan?
Yes, I will.
Jolan true.
Perhaps this is not
such a good place to talk.
So, what do you think
of your enemy, Captain Picard?
PICARD:
These people are
no one's enemy, Senator.
PARDEK:
Many of my colleagues
fear what they have to say,
but I have learned
to listen carefully.
Children like D'tan
are our future.
Old men like me
will not be able
to hold on to ancient
prejudice and hostility.
Young people won't allow it
but now,
now that they've
met their first real Vulcan
it has only inspired
them more.
I am sure that is evident
to you, Spock.
I did not anticipate
such a passionate response
to my arrival.
Romulans are
passionate people.
The Vulcans will learn
to appreciate
that quality in us.
If we are successful.
We will know soon.
The proconsul has agreed
to meet with you.
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 45245.8.
The Enterprise remains
at Qualor Two
as we continue
to investigate the theft
of a surplus Vulcan ship.
The trail has led us
to the former wife
of a deceased smuggler.
( chime music playing )
A new face.
Same one I've always had.
And what would
you like to hear?
Know some blues?
Look at me, mister.
What do you think?
Seven different
shades of them.
How about some Andorian blues?
Suck salt?
Never cared for it.
Mmm...
Good for you.
Nasty habit.
So who are you looking for?
Who says I'm looking
for anybody?
Your face, your uniform,
in a place like this.
Okay.
I'm looking for you.
Oh, you just made my day.
I have to ask
about your husband.
Well, it was nice
while it lasted.
Which husband?
The dead one, I'm afraid.
Oh, you must be
from the Enterprise.
You destroyed his ship.
He was into
some bad business.
He took the evidence with him.
His one endearing quality--
he always cleaned up
after himself.
And what do you want from me?
I was hoping you might know his
business partners.
And why should I help you?
To be honest,
I can't think of a good reason.
Well...
you did kill
my ex-husband.
And that's not a bad start.
So why don't you drop
a few coins in the jar
and I'll see
what I remember.
I don't carry money.
Well you don't offer much,
do you?
Move over.
Oh, just what I need--
another set of hands.
Know this one?
( playing blues )
20th century Earth.
Maybe I could teach you
a lick or two.
You already have.
So what do you say?
Going to be around
for a couple of days?
I can be.
Sooner or later, a man named
Omag will come by for a song.
Always wants to hear
the same thing--
"Melor Famagal."
He's an arms trader.
A fat Ferengi.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Proconsul.
Yes.
Pardek, come in.
Ambassador Spock of Vulcan.
Proconsul.
Oh, please.
I've never liked titles
ever since I was a lowly
uhlan in the Romulan guard.
I am Neral.
How is it again?
Pardek's tried
to show me.
I am honored.
Good.
Permit me to withdraw.
Will we see you and
your wife tomorrow
at the state dinner?
We're looking forward to it.
It's been years
since old Pardek's
been invited
to an official function.
He's far too attached
to the common man
for most people's comfort.
That is their loss.
I've found Pardek
to have
a unique insight
into many issues.
Let me tell
you something, Spock.
We are going to start
something here, you and I,
that will redraw the face
of the quadrant.
Are you prepared
to support reunification?
I believe
it must eventually come.
Our two worlds need each other.
Forgive me, I...
did not expect to hear
a Romulan proconsul
speak like a member
of your underground.
Well, I want you to know
exactly where I stand.
And do you believe
that you can gain the support
of your full senate?
Well, things are not what
they once were in the senate.
The old leaders have lost
the respect of the people.
Involvement
in the Klingon war...
endless confrontations
with the Federation...
they're tired of it.
Times are changing
and leaders who refuse
to change with them
will no longer
be leaders.
Spock, I am prepared
to publicly endorse
the opening of talks
between our peoples.
What do you think
the Vulcan people
will think of that?
They will be cautious.
There are generations
of distrust to overcome.
But surely with a man of your
influence leading the way...
Proconsul, the senate
has been recalled into session.
Very well.
Can we meet
again tomorrow?
As you wish.
Good.
Jolan true, Spock.
Oh...
Live long and prosper.
It's everything
we could have hoped for.
SPOCK:
It is more than
we could have hoped for.
But if Neral is ready to
publically endorse
reunification...
It is hard to believe
that he can rise to the rank
of senate proconsul
without the support of the
Romulan traditionalists.
That may be true, but...
Then how can he turn
his back on them so easily?
How can he endorse reunification
when it's considered subversive?
Because he's
not afraid of them.
He knows that we'll
support it.
Captain Picard is correct.
It is not logical
for the proconsul
to support reunification
at this time.
Why would Neral lie?
Perhaps because he's
hoping to expose
members of your movement.
No, this is our chance
for acceptance--
finally to be heard.
I believe
it's the Federation
that fears an alliance
between Romulus and Vulcan.
That is not true!
I came here to determine
the potential for reunification.
In spite of what has occurred,
I intend to continue
with my efforts.
I intend to meet
with the proconsul as planned.
You let
their emotions sway you.
On the contrary, I am pursuing
the most logical course.
You're as skeptical
as I am.
Is it logical to ignore
your own good sense?
I fear the influence of Sarek
has colored
your attitudes, Captain,
toward reunification
and perhaps toward me.
That is the second time
you have accused me of speaking
with another man's voice.
It's true he will
always be a part of me--
his experience
his spirit.
But I speak
with my own voice, not his.
Curious...
that I should hear him
so clearly
now that he is dead.
It is possible
that I have brought
my argument with Sarek
to you, Captain.
If so, I apologize.
Is it so important
that you win one last
argument with him?
No, it is not,
but it is true that
I will miss the arguments.
They were, finally,
all that we had.
But your fight with Sarek
is over, Spock.
You have none with me.
I always had
a different vision
than my father--
the ability to see
beyond pure logic.
He considered it weak.
But I have discovered it
to be a source
of extraordinary strength.
Sarek would have seen
this mission of reunification
as a fool's errand.
Somehow, I think it is not.
Logic cannot explain why.
I only know that
I must pursue this.
Even if it leads you
into a Romulan trap?
If the Romulans
do have an ulterior motive
it is in the best interests
of all concerned
that we determine what it is
so I will play the role
that they would have me play.
Have you had
any success, Mr. Data?
Negative, Captain.
The Romulan information net
employs a progressive
encryption lock.
I've been unable to penetrate
their security measures.
May I assist you,
Commander?
I have had some experience
in these matters.
By all means, Ambassador.
The Romulans have incorporated
a 43-part cipher key
into their
entry sequence.
Yes, sir.
The 29th is the only one
I cannot bypass.
I think I'll take this
opportunity to remove my ears.
He intrigues me--
this Picard.
In what manner, sir?
He's remarkably analytical
and dispassionate
for a human.
I understand why my father
chose to mind meld with him.
There's an almost
Vulcan quality to the man.
Interesting.
I had not considered that
and Captain Picard
has been a role model
in my quest to be more human.
More human?
Yes, Ambassador.
Fascinating.
You have an efficient intellect,
superior physical skills
no emotional impediments.
There are Vulcans
who aspire all their lives
to achieve what you've been
given by design.
You are half-human.
Yes.
Yet you've chosen
a Vulcan way of life.
I have.
In effect, you've abandoned
what I have sought
all my life.
I believe I have isolated
the 29th cipher access code.
I shall attempt to access
the proconsul's files.
Ambassador Spock,
may I ask a personal question?
Please.
As you examine your life
do you find you have
missed your humanity?
I have no regrets.
"No regrets."
That is a human expression.
Yes.
Fascinating.
Do you know any Klingon opera?
I don't get a lot
of requests for it.
Surely you must know
at least one theme
from Aktuh and Maylota.
I may be a little rusty.
♪ Aktuh ♪
♪ Maylota ♪
♪ Ayayhor ♪
♪ Chapayhay ♪
♪ Maylota ♪
Maylota.
♪ Maylota
Maylota ♪
♪ Maylota ♪♪
MAN:
What is that dreadful noise?!
It sounds like
a Bardakian pronghorn moose!
You know
what I want to hear.
AMARIE:
Yes, yes, I know.
( playing music )
( Amari singing
soprano trills )
Worf to Enterprise.
RIKER:
Go ahead.
A fat Ferengi has just entered
the establishment.
Is that "Melor Famagal"
I hear?
It is.
I'm on my way.
Where's the waiter?!
Is there no waiter
in this sorry place?
Is there a problem?
Yes. I need more napkins.
Use your sleeve.
What did you say?
Use one of their sleeves.
I don't care.
Who are you?
Commander William Riker,
USS Enterprise.
Oh. Am I supposed to
stand up and salute?
We're investigating
the disappearance
of a Vulcan ship.
Well, you've got
the wrong Ferengi.
I never traded Vulcan ships.
We know that you're involved.
Who would want a Vulcan ship?
Vulcans are pacifists.
I deal in warships.
Can somebody get me a napkin?!
Who would want a Vulcan ship?
Hypothetically speaking?
Hypothetically speaking.
I never learned
to speak hypothetical.
Ah!
Are you crazy?
Let me explain
what will happen to you
if you don't tell me
about the Vulcan ship.
Your right of passage
through this sector
will be revoked, and more than
that I will be very unhappy.
I delivered it
to a Barolian freighter.
At what coordinates?
I don't remember.
Ow! Watch it!
You're stretching my neck!
Coordinates?
At Galorndon Core,
near the Neutral Zone.
That's all I know.
I swear it.
Enjoy your dinner.
As soon as I heard
this Barolian ship
was at the Galorndon Core,
I started to think Romulans.
And the Romulans
are suddenly interested
in bonding with the Vulcans.
Spock has been meeting
with the new senate proconsul
about reunification.
Reunification?
The proconsul says
that he is prepared
to endorse peace talks.
And Spock?
The Ambassador
is skeptical
but he cares a great deal
about reunification.
As long as there's
a chance of success,
he's prepared
to pursue it.
I'm afraid I don't see how
a stolen Vulcan ship
fits into all of this.
Neither do I, counselor.
How soon can you be at
Galorndon Core, Number One?
A little over eight hours.
Well, this may prove
to be a wild goose chase
but I don't see that we
have any choice, do you?
Agreed.
( console beeping )
We are losing our Romulan
carrier wave, sir.
We'll advise you further
as soon as you reach your
destination, Number One.
Picard out.
Ensign, set a course
for Galorndon Core.
Take us to warp eight.
Aye, sir.
Captain,
the Romulan subspace logs
identify a transmission
from the Romulan surface
to a Barolian ship near
Galorndon Core 12 hours ago.
Galorndon Core is along
the Barolian trade route.
They trade a great deal
with the Romulans.
It's probably just routine.
This does not appear
to be routine.
I was able to trace
the source of the transmission.
It incorporates the code prefix
of Romulan intelligence.
Can you access it?
It is a short
sequence of numbers.
One-four-zero-zero.
Nothing more?
No, sir.
Spock, I've been
looking for you.
I've been meeting
with the proconsul.
Does he still speak
of reunification?
He speaks of nothing else.
Have you ever seen these?
The syllabic nucleus
of the Vulcan language.
They were my toys
when I was small.
Your parents wanted you
to learn to understand Vulcan?
Yes.
As did their parents
before them.
To prepare us for the day
when we would live again
with our Vulcan cousins.
Your friends from the Federation
have returned.
They need
to see you immediately.
I've told Pardek.
He'll meet you in the cave.
The only communication
that was sent
were the numbers
one-four-zero-zero.
What does
it mean?
It means
that the proconsul
has apparently been
attempting to deceive me.
For what purpose,
I cannot say yet
but his conversations with me
have obviously been part
of a greater plan which involves
the stolen Vulcan ship.
How do you know that,
Ambassador?
The time the proconsul set
for the subspace announcement
of our peace initiative
is 1400 hours tomorrow.
One-four-zero-zero.
Why would they
need a Vulcan ship?
SELA:
That will become clear
very shortly.
Captain Picard,
welcome to Romulus.
I trust
you've enjoyed your visit
and this is the android
I've come to respect in battle.
Lieutenant Commander Data.
How could they know
of this location?
Someone has betrayed us.
Yes, you did.
Spock...
we've been friends for 80 years.
It is the only
logical conclusion.
You asked me to come to Romulus
you arranged the meetings
with the proconsul
and you knew that
Picard and Data
had returned to the surface
with new information.
The great Spock.
Very well.
Senator Pardek, your service to
the Romulan people
is noted and appreciated.
Jolan true, Spock.
Do not be distressed.
Your dream of reunification
is not dead.
It will simply take
a different form--
the Romulan conquest of Vulcan.
Bring them.
First officer's log,
supplemental.
The Enterprise
has reached Galorndon Core
near the border
of the Neutral Zone.
Any signs of life,
Mr. La Forge?
Negative, Commander.
The Romulans could have
a cloaked base on the surface.
Or anywhere else
along the Neutral Zone.
Sir, a coded subspace
signal from Romulus.
It's the Captain.
What?
"Maintain position
at Galorndon Core.
"Diplomatic initiative
appears to be succeeding.
Will advise."
The message did employ
the proper coded sequence.
Yeah, I'm sure
it did.
SELA:
Come in, gentlemen.
Take a seat, please.
Excuse me, I'm just
finishing up a speech...
for you, Mr. Spock.
I rather enjoy writing.
I don't get to do it
very often in this job.
Perhaps you would be
happier in another job.
Please feel free to change
any words that you wish.
I've tried to make it
sound Vulcan--
a lot of unnecessarily
long words.
In a few hours,
you will deliver
this statement alongside
our senate proconsul.
It will announce to the Vulcans
that a peace envoy
is on its way from Romulus.
We will transmit it
on all Federation
subspace frequencies.
A peace envoy
in a stolen Vulcan ship?
Actually, three Vulcan ships,
Captain.
The Enterprise is only aware
of the one we stole
from Qualor Two.
We have been following
their investigation.
It has forced us
to make some minor changes--
one of them, a message
sent in your name
ordering them
to stay where they are.
The moment those Vulcan ships
enter the Neutral Zone
the Enterprise
will move to intercept.
In that event, the Enterprise
will be given more important
matters to attend to.
In the meantime,
Ambassador Spock
will be telling his people
to welcome the peace envoy.
And when they do,
our forces will seize control
before anyone realizes
what has happened.
Do you seriously believe
that the Federation
will not immediately intervene?
Of course it will, and we're
fully prepared for it.
But we will be there--
entrenched.
And it will be very difficult
to get us out once we are.
Reunification will become
a fact of life.
I will not read this
or any other statement.
If you do not,
you will die.
All of you will die.
Since it is logical
to conclude
that you will kill us
in any event
I choose not to cooperate.
I hate Vulcans.
I hate the logic.
I hate the arrogance.
Very well.
Computer, holographic
program Spock one.
By taking advantage
of holographic sampling
during the last few days
we have created
a programmable Spock.
Run program.
This is Ambassador
Spock of Vulcan.
By now,
Federation sensors
are tracking
three Vulcan ships
crossing the Neutral Zone.
These ships
carry the future
of the Romulan
and the Vulcan people.
Our long conflict
is finally over.
SELA:
Freeze.
We would have preferred
an interactive Spock
who could have
responded to questions
but this will have to suffice.
You can hardly believe
this will convince anyone.
I don't need to convince them--
just confuse them long enough
to reach Vulcan.
End program.
If you'll excuse me,
it's time to send our ships
on their journey.
Suggestions.
Commander Data,
are they still unaware
that we have access
to their computers?
I believe so, Ambassador.
Then perhaps
you and I can find a way
to create a diversion.
Sir, sensors are picking up
three vessels
crossing the Neutral Zone.
Vulcan ships.
Vulcan?
What's the heading,
Mr. Worf?
143.012.
That would put them
on a course to Vulcan.
They don't seem to be
in any hurry.
They're only moving at
warp one, Commander.
Worf, signal them
on subspace.
Request their status.
Geordi, see if you can tell if
it's one of the ships
that we've
been looking for.
They say they
are escorting
a peace envoy
from Romulus to Vulcan.
They request we monitor
Federation subspace channels.
Ambassador Spock will be making
an announcement shortly.
Perhaps his reunification talks
were successful.
Geordi?
None of
the transponder signatures
matches that
of the missing ship.
They could
have been altered.
I'll keep checking.
Set a course to intercept.
Sir, the Captain's orders
were to maintain...
I know the Captain's
orders, Lieutenant.
Engage.
Impossible.
There's no way they could have
gotten out of this room.
RIKER:
That's far enough.
Stay right where you are.
Drop your weapons.
How did you get in here?
Cease fire.
Holograms.
I'm afraid
I don't know too much
about Romulan
disrupter settings.
Cowboy diplomacy?
Well done, Mr. Data.
Though...
I don't think you got
Commander Riker's hair
quite right.
I will be more observant
in the future, sir.
It doesn't matter
what you do now
Spock's announcement
will be made in minutes.
Our forces will be on Vulcan
before you can alert anyone.
We've just received
a priority one distress call
from the colony
on Dulisian Four.
A massive failure
of the environmental
support systems.
They're going
to require evacuation.
Mr. Worf,
any other ships
in the vicinity
of Dulisian Four?
One, sir, a Rutian
archaeological vessel.
I'm sure
it's not equipped
to handle something
of this scale, Will.
Geordi, any update
on the Vulcan ships?
I've checked every sensor
display backwards and forwards.
If the Romulans
altered them
they didn't
leave fingerprints.
I can't tie any of them
to the surplus yard.
The Vulcan ships
have entered Federation space,
maintaining low warp.
Lay in a new course
to Dulisian Four.
WORF:
Incoming message
from Romulus
on all subspace channels.
On screen.
This is Ambassador Spock
of Vulcan.
By now, Federation sensors
are tracking
three Vulcan ships
crossing the Neutral Zone.
These ships carry a Romulan
invasion force
and must be stopped.
I repeat,
these ships carry
a Romulan inva...
Doctor, contact Dulisian Four
and confirm this distress call.
I have a feeling it
may prove to be a false alarm.
Mr. Worf, how long before
we intercept the Vulcan ships?
14 minutes, sir.
Communication lines
have been terminated
at the transmitter,
but I am quite certain
the message was sent
prior to the interruption.
Well done, Mr. Data.
You'll never get out
of this building.
I disagree, Commander.
After studying the design
of this structure
I have determined that
our best route of escape
would be the underground
exit to the east of this wing.
I've disconnected certain
security scanners to assist us.
I'm afraid we cannot allow you
to warn your guards.
Not bad.
The Vulcan defense vessels
are also responding.
The Romulan force is retreating
towards the Neutral Zone.
They're not taking those
Vulcan ships home with them.
Visual range, Commander.
On screen.
GEORDI:
Romulan warbird decloaking
alongside the Vulcan ships.
Red alert.
Advise the warbird to withdraw
from Federation space
and tell them to leave the
Vulcan ships where they are.
The warbird is powering up its
forward disrupter array.
Ready phasers.
There were over
2000 Romulan troops
on board those ships.
They destroyed
their own invasion force.
Rather than
let them be taken prisoner.
Stand down red alert.
Mr. Worf,
advise the Klingon ship to
signal us
as soon as Captain Picard
and Data are safely on board.
Aye, sir.
D'TAN:
This way.
Pardek never
saw these caves.
It's safe.
They won't find us here.
What will you do now?
What we have always done--
continue to teach
pass on the ideals
to a new generation
work for the day when new
thoughts may be spoken aloud.
The Federation will
welcome that day.
Captain, we will
need to reach
our transport site
in 14 minutes.
I wish you well.
Thank you.
Captain.
I will not be
coming with you.
Ambassador...
The reason
for my coming here
has never been more clear.
The union of the Vulcan
and the Romulan people
will not be achieved
by politics or by diplomacy
but it will be achieved.
The answer has been here
before us all along.
An inexorable evolution
toward a Vulcan philosophy
has already begun.
Like the first Vulcans
these people are struggling
to a new enlightenment
and it may take decades
or even centuries
for them to reach it
but they will reach it,
and I must help.
I have learned that it is
useless to argue with you
once your mind is set.
Not at all, Captain.
I have found our arguments
quite useful--
almost as useful as those
I had with my father.
Would it surprise you
to learn
that he found them
equally valuable?
Ironically...
you may know Sarek better
than his own son does.
My father and I
never chose to meld.
I offer you the chance
to touch what
he shared with me.
♪♪