Captain's Log,
Stardate 45349.1.
The Enterprise is on its way
to Penthara Four
where a type "C" asteroid
has struck
an unpopulated continent.
The resulting dust cloud could
very well create a phenomenon
not unlike the nuclear winters
of 21st century Earth.
Commander La Forge
has begun work on a plan
that would counteract
the devastation.
I'm afraid the numbers
coming in are already
indicating climatic
changes, Commander.
What kind of drop
can we expect?
If the Pentharan spheral
forecasts are correct,
10 to 12 degrees Celsius
within the first ten days.
If it continues like that,
their entire ecosystem
will be shot
to hell.
And I doubt if they
are prepared to cope with
the kind of cold
that's coming.
PICARD: Commander Riker?
Yes, sir.
Would you join me
on the bridge please?
RIKER:
Right away, sir.
Are you certain,
Mr. Worf?
There was a space-time
distortion, sir.
And there is something
back there.
We passed within
300 kilometers of it.
That's too close
to be a coincidence.
Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE:
Yes, Captain?
Would a delay of one hour
affect your plans?
Not unless another
asteroid decides
to play a call on
Penthara, sir.
The odds of that
occurring, Captain,
are extremely unlikely,
given the time frame.
Thank you, Mr. Data.
Ensign, bring
the ship about.
Let's take a look
at Mr. Worf's distortion.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf's what?
The lieutenant's sensors
have detected
a temporal distortion
almost in our current course.
There's a small object
back there
that wasn't there
a few moments ago.
The object is
50 kilometers ahead, sir.
Full stop, Ensign.
Aye, sir.
On screen.
RIKER:
Dimensions, Worf?
Approximately five meters
in length, sir.
Life signs?
No signs
of any kind.
Our sensors do not
penetrate the hull.
Try hailing it.
Now, that's odd.
What's odd?
We've received
a response, but...
Yes, Mr. Worf?
They want you
to "move over," sir.
Reply that the Enterprise isn't
going anywhere, lieutenant.
Not the Enterprise,  Captain--
you.
What are you trying
to tell me, Mr. Worf?
Oops.
Excuse me, Captain,
but you were
standing
right where
I needed to be.
Who are you?
Rasmussen's
the name, sir.
Professor Berlinghoff
Rasmussen.
Oh, this is wonderful.
Actually, quite a bit larger
than I thought.
Really?
Where I come from,
every historian knows
the bridge of old 1701-D.
And where, exactly,
do you come from?
Why, Earth.
The late 26th century
Earth, to be exact.
I've traveled back
nearly 300 years
just to find you.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Exactly what kind
of historian are you?
Oh, my focus
is on the 22nd
through the
24th centuries--
early interstellar
history.
You know, it was
always believed
this was on your desk,
not here.
Fascinating.
Don't you move it
on my account.
You can't expect me
to believe that
the layout
of my ready room
can possibly be of interest
to future historians.
Oh, no less so than your
legendary modesty, Captain.
I wish I could
describe to you
what a thrill
it is to be here.
This is the original.
You flatter me,
Professor.
But I can't help
but wonder
what could possibly
have caused you
to select me as a subject
for your study.
Even in this decade,
there are...
far wiser and more
experienced humans
in and out
of Starfleet.
I'd love to
tell you, Picard,
I really would, but...
try and imagine
what a young Caesar
might have done
differently
had someone given him
a hint of
what lay ahead,
or if Lincoln
had been coerced
into changing
his theater plans.
I truly wish
I could be more specific
on why you were selected,
but I'm afraid
the exchange of information
will have to flow
in one direction only.
Five, six, seven meters.
Ha!
I was right.
Why now?
LA FORGE: Right.
If you've come back
to study us,
to study the captain,
why did you pick today?
Why not a year ago?
Or a year from now?
Oh, I picked the right
day, all right.
Just wait. You'll see.
Um... do you always
sit there
on that side
of the table?
Usually.
Why?
It's... not important.
Professor, at what point
does time travel
become a tool
for historians?
Now, now, Commander,
you know better than that.
I've studied a great deal
about your century,
including the fact
that you're all quite aware
of the dangers of anyone
altering the past,
and that's exactly
what I'd be doing
if I were to divulge
information
like that.
Telurian plague.
Beg your pardon?
The Telurian plague--
was it cured?
I mean, did they find
the cure by your century?
Oh, it can't do any harm
to ask that.
I realize
that it's difficult,
but we must keep
to ourselves
questions
about the future.
Go on, Professor.
I'll be preparing
questionnaires for each of you.
Please complete them
at your convenience.
If you're concerned
about a possible
breach of security,
I'm sure your captain
can make a determination.
And, thank you in advance
for curbing your curiosity.
If I hand my assignment
in on time,
can I get a glimpse into
next week's poker game?
( chuckling )
Mr. Data, would you
escort the professor
to his quarters?
This way, sir.
What did he mean
he "picked the right day"?
You know everything
I do, Number One.
Deanna?
It's hard to tell, but
he is holding something back.
CRUSHER:
Well, of course
he is.
All the things
he could tell us.
he would like to tell us.
It might be that.
I don't know.
What if he's an imposter?
God knows we've seen
enough of them.
Well, he is human.
The medical scans
have proven that,
right, Doctor?
He's human,
all right.
And there was
a temporal distortion
back there, correct,
Mr. Worf?
Yes, sir.
And no one
can deny that
that ship of his
is unlike
anything
we've ever seen.
LA FORGE:
The hull is made
of some kind of
plasticized
tritanium mesh.
We've nothing like it
on record.
At least,
not until now.
Hmm.
Mr. Worf, I do
appreciate your caution.
I share it.
Bring his vessel
into the shuttle bay.
Place it under guard.
Yes, sir.
( sighs )
I realize that
this... visit
is going to be difficult
for some of us.
But I've examined
his credentials
and everything seems
to be in order,
so I think we should extend
to him every courtesy.
Including
questionnaires?
Including questionnaires,
Mr. Worf.
This is really
a thrill, Data.
Like running across
a Redstone missile,
or a Gutenberg bible.
To think-- the model "T"
of androids.
If you were referring
to the first
production model automobile
of the 20th century,
perhaps the subsequent
model "A"
would be
a more apt analogy,
since I am Dr. Noonian Soong's
revised prototype.
I stand corrected.
Is there a problem,
Professor?
Hmm, I suppose it will have
to do... for now.
I'll get you a list of the
things I'll be needing, okay?
Would I be correct,
Professor,
in assuming that you know
whether or not I am still...
alive in
the 26th century?
Since you seem
to know so much
about Captain Picard
and the ship, I assumed you--
It would be best if
you kept your assumptions
to yourself,
wouldn't it?
Yes, sir.
Sorry, sir.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45350.3.
We have arrived
at Penthara Four
and can see
for ourselves
the atmospheric devastation
caused
by the asteroid's impact.
We've located
three underground pockets
of carbon dioxide--
here, here,
and here.
Now, our drilling
phasers
can release enough of
the gas to form an envelope,
which should temporarily
hold in the heat of the sun.
We spend years, decades,
trying to avoid anything
that would lead
to a greenhouse effect,
and now here we are about to...
create one on purpose.
Less than 20% of
your normal sunlight
is getting through through
that dust, Doctor.
If we can hold enough
heat in with the CO2,
that should give
the planet time
to mend itself.
WOMAN: Excuse me, Dr. Moseley?
What now?
New Seattle's reporting
a cloud depth
of 12 kilometers.
Two rivers--
tropical rivers--
are beginning
to freeze.
We'd better get started
before there's nothing
left to mend.
RIKER:
Look who's here.
Oh.
I hate
questionnaires.
Professor!
Come and join us.
Hope I'm not intruding.
Not at all.
I'm sure you're the topic
of conversation
at every table
in this room.
Uh, as I promised,
here are your
assignments,
and I'm sure
they'll be painless.
Please try and complete
them by tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
No problem, Professor.
Ah, you're all very calm.
Is there some reason
we shouldn't be?
History always records
where people were,
what they were doing,
when important events
took place.
But it rarely remembers
their activity, say,
a week before, or a day,
or even an hour.
Are you
suggesting that
an important event
is imminent?
I didn't say that,
now did I?
Please, just go on doing
what you're doing
and pretend I'm not here.
Why is there no record
of other future historians
traveling back to witness
important events?
We're obviously
very careful.
As a matter of fact,
a colleague and I
recently paid a call
on a 22nd century
vessel.
They hadn't perfected
quarantine fields.
You probably saw some
surgical masks and gloves.
Isn't it fascinating
how everyone has
different interests
when it comes
to history.
Different perspectives
on progress.
Would you mind telling me
what that is?
Oh, just checking
the time.
No problem.
Is something important
supposed to be happening here?
Oh, no, it's nothing,
it's nothing.
What about you,
Commander?
What do you see as
the most important example
of progress in
the last 200 years?
I suppose, the warp coil.
Before there was warp drive,
humans were confined to
a single sector of the galaxy.
Spoken like
the consummate explorer.
What is going on?
Are you expecting
someone?
Phasers.
Beg your pardon?
There were no phasers
in the 22nd century.
Ah, you see, Doctor?
Our Klingon friend
is a perfect example
of what I was trying
to tell you.
He views history
through the eyes
of a hunter,
a warrior.
His passion lies
in the perfection
of the tools
of violence.
How delightfully
primitive.
As soon as we input this
atmospheric data from Moseley,
the computer should tell us how
many holes we'll have to punch.
What have you learned
about the tectonic stability
around the drilling sites?
Couldn't be better.
Our scans were all clear and
Moseley says there hasn't been
so much as a quiver down
there in well over a century.
A-ha, just the two
I'm looking for.
Um, brought you the forms
I need you to complete.
Shouldn't take anything more
than a couple of hours.
We're kind of
busy here, Professor.
Tomorrow would
probably be better.
Data, we've got about
23,000 thermal simulations.
You think you could check
them over for anomalies?
Certainly.
Is that as fast
as he can go?
Not fast enough
for you, Professor?
There's very little known
about Data's efficiency.
Almost nothing about
its part in this mission.
It's a topic of
great conjecture.
DATA:
209 anomalies,
all within acceptable
parameters.
Thanks, Data.
You're here
to witness this mission.
That's it, isn't it?
It would be best
if you just thought of me
as a fly on the wall
and went about your business.
I will have
your answered questions
as soon as possible,
Professor.
Data...
at Penthara Four!
If you'll excuse me.
Um, your prosthesis--
what do you--
what do you call it again?
A visor.
Visor, right, a visor.
You know, I have
a picture of you
wearing that
in my office.
How do you like it?
It allows me to see,
and I like it just fine.
You know,
Homer was blind.
Milton... Bach...
Monet... Wonder.
A fly on the wall,
huh?
A fly on the wall.
The computer has configured
the drilling patterns
in specified depths.
Captain, we've got
everything we need.
I'm ready to transport
down to the surface.
PICARD:
I'll notify Dr. Moseley.
Good luck, Geordi.
Gentlemen.
Who said these moments
were any less exciting
when you know
the outcome, hmm?
I know of no one
who said that, Professor.
The Enterprise will monitor
the CO2 concentrations
at six different
altitudes.
If all goes well,
it shouldn't take
more than 20
bore sites.
Let's hope all goes well.
La Forge to Commander Riker.
How are you doing?
RIKER:
We've gotten word from
the monitoring stations.
They're all online.
We're ready
when you are, Geordi.
That's excellent.
All we need now is
an open channel to Data.
Open a channel,
Mr. Worf,
and prepare
to fire at target one.
The computer has locked in
phaser depth calculations.
Mr. Data?
Ready, sir.
Fire.
Target one is emitting
2,000 cubic meters per second.
Target two, 1,600.
The surface wind patterns
over the target are stable.
You picking up anything
at altitude, Data?
DATA:
CO2 concentrations remain
unchanged at upper elevations.
Have I missed much?
Target 14 complete,
sir.
Data,
what have you got?
No change, sir.
RIKER:
How are the surface winds,
Geordi?
Holding steady, sir.
The computer
has stopped drilling.
You should be getting
something now, Data.
Elevated CO2 levels
at 20 kilometers, sir.
Now your talking.
We've got some new
temperatures coming in.
All thermal
monitoring stations
are reporting no further
temperature drops.
Correction, Doctor--
two equatorial stations
are reporting
slight increases.
Thank you.
Thank you, all.
You've given us
what we need-- time.
We're glad to
be of help, doctor.
The Enterprise
will remain in orbit
and continue to monitor
your progress.
Picard out.
"You've given us
what we need--
time."
Ensign, return
to synchronous orbit.
Aye, sir.
Very clever, Picard.
And well done.
We always knew
how you did it,
but to experience the moment,
to witness the nuances,
it's, uh...
indescribable.
He's after more than
a history lesson,
I can tell
you that.
What is it?
What are you getting from him?
I don't know.
It's like he's trying
to confuse us,
misdirect us, somehow.
RASMUSSEN:
There you are!
Well, that certainly
was exciting, wasn't it?
Professor, is everything
all right? Are you well?
Yes, couldn't be better,
thank you.
I just thought we might chat
about your questionnaire.
Buck up, crewman.
You're a credit
to that uniform.
I've got some things
to take care of.
Uh, no, please,
Counselor,
I'd very much appreciate
your remaining.
Doctor, in response
to my sixth question,
you spoke of
a neural stimulator.
May I see one?
I don't see why not.
Give me a minute.
You don't like me
very much, do you?
I don't dislike you,
Professor.
Keep your eyes wide,
soldier.
You'll be telling
your grandchildren
how you were there
at Penthara Four.
But you don't
trust me.
You should,
you know.
Should I?
"Picard's empath
won't trust you."
That's what
they all said.
Picard's empath?
We're not that unalike,
you and I.
You possess a sense that
is foreign to the others.
My knowledge of
the future is similar.
You know, some of my
best friends are empaths.
They trust me.
Why should you care whether
I trust you or not?
We're birds of a feather.
We're colleagues.
We could learn a lot
from each other.
You're right.
I don't trust you.
I knew you'd say that.
I'm sure you did.
Well, I'm glad to see you two
are finally getting along.
I really have
to be going.
Thank you.
Why don't you try
a berylite scan.
I'd be interested to see
what his micro-levels are.
So, what else
can I show you?
You're a very
curious woman.
Hmm?
No, no, I don't mean
curious like that.
I mean, you're curious...
about things.
About... berylite levels.
About... the future.
Well, curiosity
is why
all of us are
out here, isn't it?
I understand,
but you're different.
You're more... vibrant.
You're more, um...
More vibrant?
That's nice.
I like that.
You know,
whenever I travel back,
I meet very
interesting people,
men and women,
but, um...
I've never met anyone
who gave me thoughts
about not going home.
You're not
supposed to be
influencing
the past, remember?
Well...
And I am beginning
to feel
just a little
bit... influenced.
Anyway, I could be
your great, great,
great, great
grandmother.
What kind of questions did
he have for you, Number One?
All he wanted to know
about was previous starships--
what I thought was innovative
about the last Enterprise,
the one before that.
He said he wanted
to see if we had
"a grasp of
the fundamentals."
His questions to me primarily
focused on Dr. Soong's--
( alarm ringing )
Captain, I'm detecting a massive
earthquake on the surface.
Two earthquakes.
Location?
Both epicenters are beneath
the two southernmost
drill sites, Captain.
Is La Forge
still down there?
WORF: Yes, sir.
Find him.
( alarm ringing )
We've also got some volcanic
activity, pretty severe.
PICARD:
Magnify.
La Forge here, Captain.
Moseley and I are on
our way back to his lab.
Are you all right?
We're okay,
but those were pretty big, sir.
If this was earth,
I'd say around
an 8 or an 8.5 on
the Richter scale.
We're starting to see
some volcanic plumes, Captain.
( alarms ringing )
Two more eruptions.
It is likely we overestimated
the geologic stability
around the CO2 pockets,
Captain.
LA FORGE:
We're in the lab, sir.
On screen.
We're fairly well quake-proof
down here, Picard.
It's the volcanic dust
I'm worried about.
What about the dust?
The ash the volcanoes are
throwing into the atmosphere
is gonna compound
the existing problem.
In a matter of days,
there'll be no sunlight
getting through
these clouds.
MOSELEY: No amount of CO2
will help us then.
Captain, take
a look at this.
These are the coordinates
of the eruptions,
and these...
are the coordinates of
the phaser drilling sites.
The mantle is collapsing
where the pressure
was released.
LA FORGE:
Captain, Dr. Moseley and I
have a couple of ideas,
but it's gonna take some time
to sort them out.
Sort them out, Geordi.
Aye, sir.
We came here
to help these people.
And look what
we've done.
( multiple classical songs
playing loudly )
( shouting )
What in God's name is that?
Music, Professor.
Music?
Yes, sir.
Mozart's Jupiter
Symphony in C-major,
Bach's Brandenburg
Concerto #3,
Beethoven's Ninth Symphony,
Second Movement,
"Molto Vivace"
and "La Donna e Mobile"
from Verdi's  Rigoletto.
You think you could
thin it out a bit?
Computer, eliminate
program one.
program two.
Computer, eliminate
program three.
Computer, half volume.
( shouting )
How the--
( normally )
How the hell can you listen
to four pieces of music
at the same time?
Actually I am capable
of distinguishing
over 150 simultaneous
compositions.
But in order to analyze
the aesthetics,
I try to keep it
to 10 or less.
Only four today?
I am assisting
Commander La Forge
with a very complex
calculation.
It demands a great deal
of my concentration.
Hmm.
Well, I, um...
came to thank you
for answering my questions,
though I probably
should have asked you
to limit yourself
to 50,000 words.
You did ask me
to be thorough.
I realize it's hard
to believe, Data,
but very few records
of Dr. Soong's work
survived to
the 26th century,
so it would be invaluable
to myself
and other historians
if you could provide us
with some... schematics?
Certainly-- as soon as
my work here is completed.
As long as it's before
0900 tomorrow.
That's when I'll be, uh...
heading back.
WORF:
Bridge to Commander Data.
Yes, Worf?
Commander La Forge is hailing
you from the surface, sir.
Patch him through, please.
Have you rerun the phase
reversal figures, Data?
There were
no errors, Geordi.
The variance
must be no more
than .06 terawatts.
Well, I don't see
any other choice.
We'll continue to run
the numbers down here,
but I doubt we'll come up
with anything different.
You'd better inform
the captain
of the good news
and the bad news.
La Forge out.
Which do you suppose he's gonna
want to hear first?
The good news.
The motion
of the dust
has created a great deal
of electrostatic energy
in the upper atmosphere.
With a modified phaser blast,
we can create a shock front
that would encircle the planet
and ionize the particles.
That would be like striking
a spark in a gas-filled room.
With one exception, sir--
the particles would
be converted
into a high-energy plasma,
which our shields
could absorb
and then redirect
harmlessly into space.
Turn the Enterprise
into a lightning rod.
Precisely, sir.
And the bad news?
If our phaser
discharge is off
by as little as
.06 terawatts,
it would cause
a cascading
exothermal inversion.
Meaning?
We would completely burn off
the planet's atmosphere.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
While Dr. Moseley
takes La Forge's plan
to the leaders
of the colony,
I find myself weighing
the potential consequences
of a more philosophical
issue.
( door chimes )
Come.
I imagine you know why
I've asked you here.
Yeah, I have
a fairly good idea.
I'm faced
with a dilemma.
There is
a planet beneath us
which is slowly
turning to ice,
and unless we do
something about it,
I'm told that
in a matter of weeks,
thousands, maybe tens
of thousands, will die.
That would be a shame.
Yes, it would.
It would be
quite a shame.
So, um...
what's your dilemma?
Commander La Forge has
a possible solution.
The margins of error
are extremely critical.
But if successful...
there will be
no more threat.
And if it's
not successful?
Every living thing on
the planet will perish.
So, do nothing,
and thousands will die.
Do something,
and millions could die.
That's a tough choice.
Not if you were
to help me.
You're not suggesting
I tell you the outcome
of your efforts?
Oh, no!
I am not.
Everything that
Starfleet stands for,
everything that I
have ever believed in,
tells me I cannot
ask you that.
But, at the same time,
there are 20 million
lives down there.
And you know what
happened to them--
what will happen
to them.
So it seems you have
another dilemma,
one that questions
your convictions.
Well, I've never
been afraid
of reevaluating my
convictions, Professor,
and now, well, I have
20 million reasons to do so.
And why did you
ask to see me?
Because your
presence gives me
a potential access
to a kind of information
that I've never had
available to me before.
And if I am to
reexamine my beliefs,
then I must take advantage
of every possible asset.
It would have been
irresponsible of me
not to ask you here.
However you come to terms
with your beliefs, Captain,
I must tell you, I'm quite
comfortable with mine.
How can you be?
How can you be comfortable
watching people die?
Um... let me put it
to you this way.
If I were to tell you that
none of those people died,
you'd easily conclude
that you tried your solution
and it succeeded,
so you would
confidently try again.
No harm in that.
But, what if I were
to tell you they all died?
What then?
Obviously, you'd decide
not to make
the same mistake twice.
Now, what if one
of those people grew--
Yes, Professor,
I know.
What if one of
those lives
I save down there
is a child
who grows up to be
the next Adolf Hitler?
Or, Khan Singh?
Every first-year
philosophy student
has been asked
that question since
the earliest wormholes
were discovered.
But this is not a class
in temporal logic.
It's not theoretical,
it's not hypothetical,
it's real!
Surely you see that.
I see it all too well.
But you must see that
if I were to influence you,
everything in this sector,
in this quadrant of
the galaxy could change.
History-- my history--
would unfold in a way other
than it already has.
Now, what possible
incentive
could anyone offer me
to allow that to happen?
I have two choices.
Either way, one version
of history or another
will wend
its way forward--
the history you know,
or another one.
Now, who is to say
which is better?
What I do know
is that here, today,
one way millions of lives
could be saved.
Now isn't that
incentive enough?
Everyone dies,
Captain.
It's just a question
of when.
All those people
down there
died years
before I was born.
All of you
up here as well.
So you see I can't get
quite as worked up as you
over the fate
of some colonists
who for me have been dead
a very, very long time.
Of course, you know
of the prime directive,
which tells us
that we have no right
to interfere in the natural
evolution of alien worlds.
Now, I have sworn
to uphold it.
But, nevertheless,
I have
disregarded
that directive...
on more than one
occasion...
because I thought
it was the right thing to do!
Now, if you are
holding on to some
temporal equivalent
of that directive,
then isn't
it possible that
you have
an occasion here
to make an exception,
to...
to help me to choose
because it's
the right thing to do?
Are we just talking
about a choice?
It sounds to me like
you're trying
to manipulate
the future.
But every choice we make
allows us to manipulate
the future.
Do I, um...
do I invite Adrienne
or Suzanne to
the spring dance?
Do I take my holiday
on Corsica, or Risa?
A person's life,
their future,
hinges on each of
a thousand choices.
Living is making
choices.
Now you ask me to believe
that if I make a choice
other than the one
that appears
in your history books,
then your past will be
irrevocably altered.
Well, you know,
Professor,
perhaps I don't give
a damn about your past
because your past
is my future.
And as far as I'm concerned,
it hasn't been written yet!
RIKER:
Captain, the electrostatic
conditions are about as good
as they're going to get.
If we're going to try this,
now is the time.
Please don't ask me,
Captain.
I can't help you.
I'm sorry.
How long will it take
to program
the phasers, Number One?
We've just got to
tie into
Geordi's
atmospheric sensors.
So you've made
your choice after all...
and without my help.
Oh, on the contrary,
Professor.
You were quite helpful.
How's that?
By refusing
to help me,
you left me with
the same choice
I had to begin with--
to try, or not to try,
to take a risk,
or to play it safe.
And your arguments
have reminded me
how precious the right
to choose is.
And because I've never been
one to play it safe...
I choose to try.
Mr. Data...
program
the firing sequence.
Aye, sir.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45351.9.
Doctor Moseley has met
with the colony leaders
who all agree they are willing
to take the risk.
Warp power
has been rerouted
from the main deflector dish,
Commander.
Keep those phasers on
active surge control, Worf.
We're only going to get
one shot at this.
Well, this is it.
You have the sequence
locked in, Data?
Yes, sir.
After an 8.3 second
burst from the dish,
we will discharge
all E.P.S. taps
through the phasers.
It's time for you to return
to the ship, Mr. La Forge.
Mr. O'Brien stand by
to transport.
Excuse me, Captain,
but I can be
of a lot more help
down here.
We're gonna have to
compensate for
the density variations
right up to the last second.
Dr. Moseley's computers
can accomplish the same
task, sir, but I believe
Geordi would be better able
to anticipate
unexpected variances.
Mr. La Forge, you know
better than anyone that
there's no guarantee
that this will work.
And if it fails...
There's no guarantee
it's going to fail, Captain.
I'd like your permission
to remain here on the surface.
Permission granted.
La Forge remained below.
Good luck, Commander.
Thank you, Captain.
DATA:
The deflector dish
has been reconfigured, sir.
Proceed, Mr. Data.
DATA:
Stand by for
auto-phaser interlock.
Activating
deflector beam.
E.P.S. taps online.
Phasers firing.
Activating shield invertors...
now.
Mr. La Forge?
La Forge here.
Still breathing,
Captain.
MOSELEY:
We've got particulate levels
right where they're
supposed to be,
and the sun is shining.
See, Captain?
I told you
there was nothing
to worry about.
Report back to the ship
when you're ready, Commander.
Doctor, we'll stay
in orbit
and analyze the remaining
volcanic disturbances,
but the best advice
will be
to... let them cool down
on their own.
I'm getting in the habit
of thanking you, Picard.
Well, I'd love
to see more,
but it's nearly
time for me to go.
I am tickled pink
to have had
the opportunity
of witnessing this, Picard.
And you did it all
without any help.
Well, I must run.
I've got some
packing to do.
You know, you're taller
in person, Commander.
Well, would you
look at this.
Who would have expected
a teary farewell?
I'm afraid we're going
to have to take
a look inside
your vessel.
Curious till the end,
eh, Captain?
You can't be serious,
Picard.
We've been through this
more than once.
A number of objects have
been discovered missing
in the last two days,
and if they're
in your possession,
then we would
like them returned.
I'm not here
in search of relics.
I'm sure
they'll turn up.
If you will not
open the vessel,
I will-- with explosives,
if necessary.
I doubt you have
the means.
If we don't get in that thing,
I guarantee you don't either.
Considering the sensitive
nature of my equipment,
I think you'll understand
if I request
that only Mr. Data
be allowed to see it.
Why Data?
Because if I order
Mr. Data never to divulge
what he sees in there,
he won't--
with the exception of anything
that might belong to us.
Understood, sir.
Back in a minute.
DATA:
I do not believe
any of these items
belong to you,
Professor.
Nor does this.
This phaser is set at
the highest stun setting.
If I'm correct,
that is sufficient
to immobilize even you.
Why have you stolen
these objects?
To put in a museum?
Oh, they're far too
valuable for that.
You see, in the century
I come from,
they haven't even
been invented yet.
But this vessel, and
the temporal distortion
that coincided
with your arrival...
Oh, this is a time pod,
and it is from
the 26th century.
At least, that's what
the poor fellow said.
You see, he decided
to travel
back to
the 22nd century--
that's my time--
and he had the misfortune
of meeting me.
His clothes fit quite
well, don't you think?
It took me weeks to figure out
how to work this thing.
Then you are not
an historian?
Mm, more of an inventor.
Up till a few weeks ago,
a dismally unsuccessful one.
What are your
intentions, Professor?
Well, thanks
to your captain,
its seems my intentions
have changed slightly.
I was quite content
with the notion of...
returning with
these trinkets.
I'd "invent" about
one a year.
But now, look what fortune
has graced me with.
You will take
a little longer
to figure out than
a tricorder,
but it should be
well worth the effort.
If the auto-timer is programmed
the way I think it is,
in about two minutes,
we should be on our way
back to a place
called... New Jersey.
I'm afraid you won't
be awake for the ride.
I assume your hand print
will open this door
whether you are
conscious or not.
That weapon was working
yesterday.
DATA:
You were right
to suspect him, sir,
but he is not
from the future.
He is from
the past.
Trying to make
my history unfold
in a way other than it
already has, eh, Professor?
This was all
a misunderstanding, Picard.
Just let me back in there.
We'll forget
the whole thing.
Now what possible incentive
could anyone
offer me
to allow that?
I believe you will
find all of
the missing items
in the vessel, sir.
Doctor...
Very nice performance.
Not all of it.
Some of it was real.
Captain...
He claims to be a 22nd
century inventor, Captain.
A pity you weren't
a bit more inventive.
If fewer things
had disappeared,
we might never
have suspected you.
As it was, the only stumbling
block was your ship.
Our sensors
couldn't penetrate it,
but once the door
was opened,
the computer was able
to detect and deactivate
everything you'd stolen,
including this.
I'd love to hear more,
Picard,
but I really must
get back in that pod.
Take him to
a detention cell,
Mr. Worf,
and notify Starfleet
that we'll be dropping him off
at Starbase 214.
WORF: Aye, sir.
You can't do this.
I've got to get back.
I don't belong here.
No!
I'm sure that there are
more than a few
legitimate historians
at Starfleet
who will be quite eager
to meet a human from your era.
PICARD:
Oh, Professor?
Welcome to
the 24th century.