Captain's Log,
Stardate 45376.3.
We're approaching
the planet Bilana III
where a new method
of propulsion
known as the "soliton wave"
is being developed.
The Enterprise has been asked
to participate
in one of the first tests
of this new technology.
Data.
Data, isn't this exciting?
We are going to witness
a moment in history.
Every nanosecond
in this continuum
is a moment in history
once it has elapsed.
No, no, no.
I mean we are going
to see something
that people will talk about
for years.
I mean, think about it
no more bulky warp engines
or nacelles.
A ship just generates
a soliton wave
and then rides it
through space
like a surfboard.
This is going to be like
being there
to watch Chuck Yeager
break the sound barrier
or Zefram Cochrane
engage the first warp drive.
It should be interesting.
Very exciting.
I'm talking
to the wrong crowd.
Donaldson.
Donaldson, you're
an engineer.
OFFICER:
Lieutenant Worf, you have
a subspace communication
from the transport ship Milan.
Transfer the signal
to this station.
Hello, Worf.
Mother.
I hope you don't mind us
dropping in on you like this
but when I heard the Enterprise
was to be in this sector
we took the first transport,
and here we are.
Is Father with you?
No, but I-I-I brought
Alexander with me.
I thought the two of you
would like the chance to visit.
Very well. I will make
arrangements
for you to come aboard.
Good.
Worf.
It's so good to see you.
You look wonderful.
Is that a touch of
gray in your beard?
Don't worry.
The Rozhenko men have always
had beards of iron gray.
Hello, Alexander.
Hello.
It's good to see you both.
How long can you stay?
I'm not going back.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Did you see the look
on Alexander's face
when he saw the play area?
He's going to love it here.
Mother, why does Alexander
believe he is remaining?
Lapsang souchong tea, please.
Are you eating?
You look thin.
Mother.
When your father
was in Starfleet
I always had to make
sure that I was...
Mother
we need to talk
about Alexander.
Alexander is a,
is a fine boy, Worf.
He's, he's smart and
he's high-spirited--
a lot like you
were at that age.
And sometimes, when he comes
running through the house
and he knocks over
that big green lamp
just like you used to do.
Well, I don't
remember you smiling
when I knocked over
that lamp.
Well, maybe once...
when you
weren't looking.
When we learned Alexander
was to come to live with us
we were so happy.
The house had been so empty
since you left
and we thought,
"here is our chance
to fill it with the sound
of children again."
But the truth is, Worf,
your father and I,
we're getting old.
Mother, you both
have many years.
Oh, I don't mean
we're ready for the grave.
Not yet anyway, but...
we're a little less active
and it's harder for us
to keep up with Alexander.
We're ready to be
just grandparents.
Alexander needs to be
with his father, Worf.
Mother, that is not possible.
We must find another option.
He needs his father, Worf.
Alexander's...
he's having difficulties.
Difficulties?
He's disobedient.
Mother...
Klingon children
are often difficult to control.
I do know something about
how Klingon children behave.
It's not just his
willful attitude.
He doesn't always
tell the truth.
My son is a liar?
He is a boy, Worf
and-and boys sometimes
take the wrong path.
They need guidance.
He needs a father--
his father--
to give him
that guidance.
I have to leave soon.
The transport will be
leaving for Earth.
You must do what you think
is best for him.
That's all a parent
can hope to do.
Did you enjoy going
to school on Earth?
Yes.
Did you like your teachers?
Good.
I understand you lived
in my old room.
Uh-huh.
Good.
Come in.
Lieutenant Worf.
Very nice to
see you again.
And you must be
Alexander.
I hear you'll be coming
to school with us for a while.
Well, we're very excited
to have you with us.
I know the other
boys and girls
will be happy
to have a new classmate.
Uh, first, I need to get
some information
from you.
Let's start with...
your name.
Alexander... Rozhenko.
Hmm. That's a tough one.
Maybe you could help me
with that.
Could you spell
your last name for me?
Alexander.
The teacher
asked you a question.
It doesn't matter.
I think I can figure it out.
Date of birth.
( sighing )
The 43rd day of Maktag,
Stardate 43205.
Yes.
Yes, of course.
I'll get
the rest
of his personal records
from the school on Earth.
And, oh, one last question.
How long will he be staying
aboard ship?
It has not been decided.
( door chimes )
Come.
Mr. Worf, I thought
our meeting
was scheduled
for 1100 hours.
I apologize for being late,
Captain.
I was detained
in school.
I-I was enrolling my son
in class.
I see.
Well, Mr. Worf,
as you are aware
several new security officers
will be transferred
into the Enterprise next week
and I would like to discuss...
Kyle to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here.
I'm sorry to bother you again,
Lieutenant, but I forgot
to mention
that we need to arrange
for a series of placement
examinations for Alexander.
If you could...
This is not a good time.
I will contact you shortly,
Ms. Kyle.
Sorry, Captain.
I would like to discuss
with you the specific areas
of ship security
that I would like...
Sick Bay to Worf.
Yes, Doctor?
I need to schedule a physical
examination for Alexander.
I also need his complete
medical records from Earth
and the medical records
of his...
I would rather discuss this
at a later time.
There's no rush.
Crusher out.
Mr. Worf, you are not
the first officer on this ship
to have a new family member.
Take care of your son.
The security
matters can wait.
Thank you, Captain.
23 field coils
working in concert
will generate
the soliton wave
from this point on
the planet surface.
We will have
our test ship
towed to a position
approximately two million
kilometers from Bilana III.
If our theories are correct
the wave will envelope the ship
and push it into warp.
Warp without warp drive.
They're going to put you
out of a job, Geordi.
I hope so, Commander.
DATA:
Dr. Ja'Dar
how closely
will the Enterprise
need to follow
the test vehicle?
The soliton emits a great deal
of subspace radio interference.
You'll need to remain
within 20 kilometers
in order to receive telemetry.
Doctor, how will you end
the experiment?
The wave will be directed
toward Lemma II
about three
light-years' distance.
Our sister facility there
will generate a scattering field
which will dissipate the wave
and bring the ship
out of warp.
I'll be sending you more
detailed operational plans
within the hour.
Very well, Doctor.
We'll contact you again
when we've finished
studying
the mission specs.
Worf.
I was just talking to Mrs. Kyle,
the primary school teacher.
She told me you'd
enrolled Alexander
in her class
this morning.
Yes.
I'm sure he'll
do very well.
She's a wonderful teacher.
Good.
Did she tell you about the
father/son
field trip this
afternoon?
Yes. We cannot attend.
Why not?
I have a personnel review
scheduled
at 1300 hours.
This would be
a good opportunity
for you to meet
some of the other
students and parents.
Well, I might be able
to reschedule the review.
Good.
I'll let them know
you're coming.
KYLE:
As the value
of their horns increased
the number of white rhinos
in the wild kept falling
until they finally became
extinct about two centuries ago.
Now, I'd like to show you
a pair of animals
that we're trying
to save from extinction.
Would you follow me?
( quiet conversations )
They're from Corvan II
where their homes
in the rain forests
are being threatened
by industrial pollutants.
They're called Corvan gilvos.
Well, they're a little shy.
Oh...
Wow.
The eating habits
of the gilvos
are very similar to those
of Earth's Draco lizards
which died out
over 300 years ago.
There are only 14 gilvos
left on Corvan II.
We're transplanting
these two
to the protected
planet Brentalia
where they
should thrive.
Well, why don't you all have
a look around
on your own for a while
and if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
Alexander
I'm sorry. I forgot
to tell everyone
that the models
on the tables
were for everyone to play with.
So I guess you didn't know you
weren't supposed to take them.
I saw you playing
with the lizard model
a while ago.
Do you still
have it?
Are you accusing him
of stealing?
Lieutenant Worf,
I can only tell you...
Alexander.
Did you take the model
of the lizard from the table?
No, sir.
Lieutenant
I saw Alexander put the model
inside of his jacket.
Lieutenant Worf, Personal Log,
Stardate 45376.8.
Alexander has acted shamefully
and, as his father,
I must now deal with him
but I find that I would rather
fight ten Balduk warriors
than face one small child.
A Klingon's honor
is more important to him
than his life.
A Klingon would gladly face
the most horrible punishment
rather than bring shame
or disgrace to his family name.
His word is his bond.
Without it, he is nothing.
Do you understand?
Why did you lie to me?
I don't know.
Did you fear the punishment
you would receive?
I don't know.
You don't know why you lied,
and yet you did.
You don't know why you stole
and yet you did!
Alexander, come here.
When I was a child,
younger than you
I lost my parents...
my family...
my people.
Everything I had
was taken from me
except my sense of honor.
It was the one thing I had
that was truly Klingon
which no one
could take away.
Do you know
who they are?
Kahless?
And his brother Morath.
They fought
for 12 days and 12 nights
because Morath
had broken his word
and brought shame
to his family.
When you lie or steal,
you not only dishonor yourself
but your family.
You dishonor me.
I'm sorry, Father.
I won't do it
ever again.
I promise.
I accept your word.
We will not speak of this again.
Worf?
Counselor.
I just wanted to know
how the field trip
went yesterday.
You have not heard?
No. Why?
Bridge.
There was an... incident.
Alexander stole a small model
and then told
a falsehood
but I have remedied
the situation.
May I ask how?
I pointed out his error
told him about
Kahless and Morath
and explained
the value of honor.
The boy understood.
I see.
Sometimes these things
aren't over
as quickly as they seem to be.
I'd be happy to help
if you have
any further
problems.
Thank you.
That will not be necessary.
Alexander will not repeat
this mistake.
DATA:
The prototype has been
towed into position, Captain.
RIKER:
Initiate a radio link
to the ship.
LA FORGE:
Link established.
Receiving prelaunch
telemetry now.
Incoming message
from Dr. Ja'Dar.
On screen.
Captain, we're ready to begin
the launch sequence.
Mr. Riker.
RIKER:
All science labs standing by.
Course laid in, sir.
PICARD:
The Enterprise
is ready, Doctor.
This is Dr. Ja'Dar
to all stations.
You may begin
the launch sequence.
And, Doctor...
good luck.
Thank you, Captain.
DATA:
Sensors indicate
the field generators
on the planet surface
are charging, Captain.
The soliton wave
has been initiated.
It's heading for the test ship.
The test ship
has successfully
entered warp, sir.
Ensign, engage.
Ensign, bring us to within
20 kilometers of the test ship.
Aye, sir.
Telemetry looks good.
Soliton wave is steady.
The test ship is maintaining
at warp 2.35, sir.
That's a little faster
than they anticipated
but still,
well within mission parameters.
We're at 20 kilometers, Captain.
Mr. Data, is the wave
affecting our warp drive?
No, sir.
The effect has been localized
to within
two kilometers
of the wave front.
Mr. La Forge, what's the power
efficiency of the wave?
Energy transfer
is... 98%!
RIKER:
98?
LA FORGE:
Yes, sir. There's less than
two percent energy loss
between the wave and the ship.
That is 450%
more efficient
than our own warp drive.
Astonishing.
Commander Riker, have
Science Lab Three
begin a series of
gamma emission tests.
Sir, the wave's power signature
is fluctuating.
Wave efficiency
has dropped to 73%.
The test ship's warp field
is becoming unstable.
Sensors show multiple
disruptions.
I'm reading a severe
subspace distortion, sir.
It is expanding
toward us.
It appears to be interfering
with our engines, Captain.
I can't compensate for it!
Bring us out of warp,
Ensign. All stop.
Aye, sir.
All stop.
Hold on!
RIKER:
Damage report.
LA FORGE:
Sensors and warp
drive are off-line.
Deflectors
down to 15%.
WORF:
Several injuries
reported on deck 27.
No fatalities.
What happened
to the test ship?
Our last readings indicate
the craft exploded
due to extreme shearing stress.
Incoming message from
Bilana III, Captain.
On screen.
Captain, are you all right?
Was anyone hurt?
We sustained
some minor damage.
Do you know what happened?
The preliminary data
we've received
indicate
a transient power imbalance.
That would be consistent
with our telemetry readings
from the ship.
We detected a sudden drop
in transfer efficiency
just before the explosion.
Are you still tracking the wave?
No. The explosion damaged
our main sensor array
but I think we'll have it
repaired in a couple of hours.
We'll contact you as soon
as the sensors are back on line.
LA FORGE:
Doctor...
you did it--
warp without warp drive.
For a while there,
it was really something to see.
Well, I hope you're here
to see it
next time we try, Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE:
So do I, Doctor.
I apologize.
I was detained.
It's quite all right.
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
Lieutenant, your son
is a very bright
very spirited young man.
From his test scores
I'm sure he'll turn out
to be one of my best students.
However, from his behavior
in class so far
I do have
some concerns.
What sort of concerns?
Frankly, he's defiant.
He's overly aggressive
toward the other students
and he has a great deal
of difficulty
paying attention.
Perhaps you do not
have experience
dealing with Klingon children.
They require a firm hand.
And he seems to still have
difficulty telling the truth.
He takes toys from
the other students
and then denies
taking them.
He acts like a bully
and then says someone else
started the fight
and he's bluntly
told me you said
"Klingons do not listen
to teachers."
I did not tell him that.
No, of course not.
He's acting
on his internal feelings
and then making up stories
to explain them.
It might be a good idea
for the two of you to sit down
with Counselor Troi
and try...
Computer,
where is Alexander Rozhenko?
Alexander Rozhenko
is on Holodeck Four.
Lieutenant, I-I
think we should...
I will handle this.
Computer,
what program is being run?
Calisthenics program
of Lieutenant Worf.
Difficulty level: novice.
( growling )
( grunting )
( grunting with exertion )
Computer, freeze program.
Did you see it, Father?
I won!
Yes, I saw.
Why are you here?
I'm training.
But you did not ask permission
to take my bat'leth
or permission to use
the holodeck.
But you said you wanted me
to be a warrior.
I also said I wanted you
to obey your teachers
and keep your promise to me.
Ms. Kyle told me
about your behavior...
about your lies.
I have not lied!
Alexander, do not continue to...
She's lying!
She hates me.
That's why she makes up stories
about me.
I will not listen to more lies.
Return to our quarters.
But you said we could go
see the gilvos again.
Not now, not after you have
broken your word.
You promised.
You said that we could.
Enough!
It is now clear to me
that I have failed in my duties
as your father.
You have no understanding
about what it means
to be Klingon.
I will arrange for you
to attend a Klingon school.
There you will learn the lessons
I have failed
to teach you.
No. I won't go!
Would you further dishonor
our family
with your disobedience?
No, sir.
You will go to our quarters
and remain there until I return.
Riker to Engineering.
What's your estimate
on the engines, Geordi?
I need another hour, Commander.
I still have to replace
three power couplings.
Understood.
Sir, sensors are
coming back on line.
Good.
Begin a sensor sweep
for the soliton wave.
Aye, sir.
The wave is continuing
on a course
to the Lemma II colony.
It is bearing
020 mark 329.
Open a channel back here
to Dr. Ja'Dar.
Sir, the wave
has increased in velocity
to warp 4.1.
Doctor, we've located
the soliton wave.
It's still on a course
to Lemma II.
However, the velocity has
increased to warp 4.1.
Have you checked the
frequency resonance
of the subspace...?
Sir, the energy level
of the wave has increased
by a factor of 12.
At this rate, it will have
increased by a factor of 200
by the time it
reaches Lemma II.
Will we still be able
to dissipate the wave?
Commander, at
that energy level
the wave will not only destroy
the colony
it'll take most of the planet
with it.
Are you sure
this is what you want?
It is not a question
of what I want.
It is a question
of what is best for the boy.
He will be better off
at a Klingon school.
Have you discussed this
with Alexander?
He is a child.
I informed him
of my decision.
I see.
You disapprove.
I'm not here
to approve or disapprove
of the way you raise your son.
My concern right now
is how this decision
is going to affect you.
How will you feel
when Alexander's gone?
I will be pleased
that he is receiving
the guidance he requires.
Is that how you felt
when he left to live
with your parents?
That was different.
At the time, I felt he needed
a home, a family--
the things I could not provide
for him.
I understand.
The idea of raising a child
can seem a tremendous burden
especially to a solitary parent.
He was no burden.
I simply knew
that a Klingon child
required more... attention
than I could provide.
I see.
Have you ever wondered
how Alexander felt
about being sent away?
He was... very young.
I am sure that he was confused.
Do you think he felt abandoned?
After all
he left very soon
after K'Ehleyr's death.
In a way, he not only
lost his mother
he lost his father
as well.
Are you saying
that his misconduct
is a result
of feeling abandoned?
It's possible.
Children don't have
the experience
to handle emotional crises.
Instead of dealing
with their feelings
they act on them.
Tell me about the last time
you spoke with K'Ehleyr...
the night she died.
We argued.
About what?
Alexander.
About how she did not
tell me about him
when he was born.
So you were angry with her.
Yes.
Are you still angry with her?
Of course not.
It would be very normal
to be angry with her--
angry because she died
and left you alone
with a son
you never knew you had.
Being angry doesn't mean
you loved her any less, Worf,
but you can't hide
from your feelings
just as Alexander
can't hide from his.
You both have
a lot of healing to do.
Perhaps you should think
about doing it together.
( door opens )
Alexander...
I'm almost done.
Stop for a moment.
Let us talk.
Why?
I want you to understand
why you are going away.
I understand.
You're ashamed of me.
You do not understand.
I'm concerned
about your future.
A Klingon school will be
a better environment for you.
You don't care about me.
That is not true.
All you care about is
your honor.
Alex...
If your mother were here
I do not think that she would
want us to fight like this.
My mother wouldn't send me away.
RIKER:
Lieutenant Worf
please report
to the observation lounge.
Acknowledged.
Remain here.
I will return shortly.
( breathing heavily )
Report.
The soliton wave
has continued
to increase in...
Excuse me.
DATA:
The soliton wave
has continued
to increase in power.
Its energy level has risen
by a factor of 96.
At its current rate of
acceleration, the wave
should hit the planet
in a couple of hours.
How do we stop it?
Well, there are
two possibilities.
We could attempt to use
our own warp engines
to generate an
inverse resonance wave.
If we could match the exact
frequency and amplitude
of the soliton, then
we should be able
to neutralize it.
You don't sound very confident.
DATA:
Because the soliton is
constantly changing
in both frequency and amplitude
it will be extremely difficult
to achieve an exact match.
Let's hear the second option.
Well, it's a little
more dangerous
but I think there's a
better chance for success.
We could create a backfire--
an explosive force set off
just in front
of the soliton wave.
A large enough explosion,
say five photon torpedoes
should be enough to
disrupt the wave
and allow it to dissipate.
How fast is
the wave traveling now?
Warp 6.37, Sir.
The good news is
we can catch it
but the bad news is
that in order to set up
this backfire
we have to be
in front of it.
Which would require the
Enterprise
to go through the wave.
Why can't we go around it?
The wave has been growing
in size as well as power.
There's insufficient time
remaining for us
to circumvent it
before it reaches Lemma II.
How much protection
will the shields provide
if we attempt to penetrate
the wave?
The shields have not been
fully restored.
Shield strength is down
to 33%.
It's going to be quite a ride.
( sighing )
It's the better choice.
Lay in a course
for the soliton wave.
Ensign, after we've passed
through the wave
I want you to take us
to a relative position
23 kilometers
in front of it.
Aye, sir.
Alert Sick Bay to prepare
for possible casualties.
Aye, sir.
The wave has increased in speed
to warp 7.2., Captain.
Ensign, take her
to warp 7.21.
We're approaching the wave,
Captain. Distance...
200 kilometers.
Let's see it.
PICARD:
Stand by to increase speed
to warp 7.3--
on my mark.
Red Alert!
Load torpedo bays.
Set warhead yields
to level 16.
Aye, sir.
All decks, this is the Bridge.
Brace for impact.
Torpedoes loaded.
Engage.
( squeaky trilling )
Report.
DATA:
We have passed through
the wave, Captain.
We have dropped
to warp 7.2.
The wave is directly astern
at a distance of 23 kilometers.
WORF:
Deflector strength
is down to 12%.
There are fluctuations in
several warp transfer conduits.
Tractor beams
and transporters off-line.
We have some gaps
in the aft shields, Captain.
When the torpedoes explode
these areas
will be contaminated
with ion radiation.
We need to evacuate
sections 24 to 47
decks 35 to 38.
Make it so.
WORF:
Sir, there is a fire
in Biolab Four.
The fire suppression apparatus
is not functioning.
Seal off
that compartment.
Prepare to vent
the air...
Sir, there are life-forms
present in that biolab.
We're transporting endangered
animals from Corvan II.
DATA:
Readings also indicate
the presence
of a humanoid, Captain.
Computer, identify
humanoid life-form
in Biolab Four.
Life-form is identified
as Alexander Rozhenko.
Bridge to Biolab Four.
Alexander,
can you hear us?
Sensors show he is alive.
He may be injured.
Can we transport him
out of there?
Transporters are still off-line.
Captain,
warp power is dropping.
We're losing speed.
Riker to Engineering.
Geordi, what is going on?
We lost four warp transfer
conduits, Commander.
RIKER:
The wave is gaining on us.
We need more speed.
LA FORGE:
I doubt that I can keep
this speed up
much longer, Commander.
You'd better
fire those torpedoes
while we're still in front
of the wave.
Mr. Data, how long
before the wave
overtakes us?
At our current speed,
four minutes
30 seconds, sir.
Captain, permission
to leave the Bridge.
Granted. Commander,
will you accompany Mr. Worf
to Biolab Four.
DATA:
Captain, Biolab Four
is one of the areas
that will be flooded
with ion radiation.
Commander, I can't let the
soliton wave hit the colony.
You have three minutes,
not one second more.
Primary control's shorted out.
( grunting )
Stand clear.
( alarm wailing )
WORF:
Alexander!
RIKER:
Can you hear me?
Alexander!
The soliton wave has closed
to ten kilometers, Captain.
Stand by to fire torpedoes
on my command.
RIKER:
Alexander!
Commander, I've found him.
Worf!
Where are you,
Worf?
Over here.
( coughing )
Help me.
It's too heavy. I've got to
find something to help us.
( groaning )
Father?
Be still. I am here.
My leg hurts.
I'm scared.
The gilvos!
There's no time.
Please! They'll die!
The wave has closed
to one kilometer, Captain.
Picard to Commander Riker.
Bridge to Lieutenant Worf.
Acknowledge.
The wave
is about to overtake us, sir.
Commander Riker, acknowledge!
Fire torpedoes.
( all coughing )
The wave has been
disrupted, sir.
Picard to Riker.
Riker here, Captain.
We made it, sir.
The boy's going
to be all right.
You're a very
lucky little boy.
Just some minor
smoke inhalation
and a hairline
fracture of the tibia.
That's a bone in your leg.
I'd like to keep him
here overnight
but he should be
fine by tomorrow.
Thank you, Doctor.
Are you going to get in trouble
because of me?
Do not concern yourself
with that.
Am I in trouble?
Yes...
but we will discuss that
at a later time.
I'm sorry.
I promise I'll be good
at the Klingon school.
I'll make you proud of me.
Klingon schools are designed
to be difficult.
The physical
and mental hardships
faced by the students
are meant to build
character and strength.
However...
if you wish to face
a greater challenge
you may stay here with me.
It will not be easy...
for either of us
but perhaps we can
face the challenge together.
I accept your challenge, Father.
I will stay.
I believe your mother
would be pleased.