Captain's Log,
Stardate 45397.3.
Two days ago
Starbase 514 lost contact
with the research
vessel Vico
which was sent to explore
the interior
of a black cluster.
We are en route
to investigate.
Captain,
we're entering Sector 9-7.
I'm picking up massive
gravitational fluctuations, sir.
Take us out of warp,
Ensign.
Yes, sir.
The black cluster is within
visual range, Captain.
On screen.
Aye, sir.
RIKER:
Let's find that ship.
Full sensor sweep,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
Quite a sight.
One of the most ancient
formations in the galaxy.
DATA:
I have located the Vico, sir.
The vessel appears
to be adrift.
Let's see it.
Life signs?
WORF:
Nothing, Commander.
Damage report,
Mr. Data.
Outer and inner hulls
have been breached.
Decks seven through 12
are exposed to space.
Set up a translink
to their computer core.
Let's see
what happened.
I cannot, sir.
The emergency bulkheads
on that deck are in place.
Our link-up signal
cannot penetrate them.
Structural status,
Commander?
Stress readings indicate
considerable pressure
on the transverse
supports.
Is it stable enough
for an away team?
Yes sir, but the risk
of structural collapse
is quite high.
Have Transporter Room One
maintain a lock
on each member
of your away team.
I want you out of there
at the first sign of trouble.
Take us to
15,000 meters, Ensign.
Yes sir.
Data, you're with me.
This station is
inoperable, sir.
This one seems to be
stuck in a feedback loop.
Let's see if we can tap directly
into the computer core.
The O.D.N. Injunction
is right down here.
Data?
Core transfer
is engaged.
Exchange protocol
verified.
The files are intact--
at least some of them anyway.
(weak male voice)
Stay here, Geordi.
Data?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise .
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
A young boy, shielded
from our initial sensor scans,
has been discovered hidden
beneath a fallen beam.
The degree of damage
to the Vico
is making our rescue attempt
difficult.
Transporter Room One,
can you lock onto him
and transport directly
to Sick Bay?
I'll try, Captain
but there's a lot of shielding
to pull him through.
Acknowledged.
Picard to Crusher.
Sick Bay here,
Captain.
PICARD:
Prepare for emergency transport.
Yes, sir.
Crusher out.
Picard to Commander Riker.
Is the boy ready,
Number One?
Ready, sir.
At your signal.
Aye, captain.
It's going
to be okay.
Here we go.
Energize.
PICARD:
Ensign, do we have him?
The lock is holding.
I just can't resolve
the matter stream--
not with all that
victurium alloy in the way.
Commander Riker, you'll have to
get him out into the corridor.
DATA:
I could move the beam, sir.
However, it may
initiate the collapse
of the surrounding
supports.
I recommend you and Geordi
return to the ship.
Agreed.
La Forge.
I'm locked onto
commander Data
and the boy, sir,
I'll energize as soon as
they've cleared
the bulkheads.
Whenever you're ready,
Data.
DATA:
Yes, sir.
You're going
to lift that?
Yes.
Then I will take you
to the corridor.
We will transport back
to the Enterprise from there.
Do you understand?
How come you can pick up
something so heavy?
I am an android.
My strength is many times
that of a human.
It is going to be...
okay.
I will count to three.
One... two...
three.
Energize.
Don't be afraid.
Captain's log,
supplemental.
A thorough
search of the Vico
has revealed no
additional survivors.
We have begun the process
of counseling the boy
with regard
to the tragedy.
We were in
the black cluster.
I don't know
where they came from.
They had a big ship.
Then they kept
shooting at us.
Then they beamed over.
They had purple helmets on
and phaser rifles.
I saw them.
They didn't see me.
You're safe now,
Timothy.
I'm sorry for
what happened.
It's going to be
all right.
I bet you're hungry.
Would you like me to get
you something to eat?
Counselor,
I must join
Commander La Forge
in Engineering.
If you will excuse me.
Timothy,
would you like Data
to stay with you
a little bit longer?
Sections of the primary
and secondary hull
were torn right off.
The shearing planes
are here, here...
and here.
How much longer until
we can access their logs?
Almost an hour.
PICARD:
The boy was here.
Mm-hmm. The hallway
outside the computer core.
His mother was the ship's
systems engineer.
The second away team
found her body here
inside the core.
And his father?
Ship's second officer.
He was most likely
on the bridge
when it was
exposed to space.
Most likely.
He'll sleep for
a few hours, at least.
I don't need
to keep him here,
but I will need to
see him again tomorrow.
You've got your work
cut out for you.
His world is gone, Data.
We're going to have to help him
build a new one.
This is not good.
Whatever hit the Vico must
have set up an e.m. pulse
that flashed through
their computer banks.
Nearly 83% of their
records have been lost.
And all of their
sensor logs.
Let's use what we got
from our own sensors.
I'll call up
the structural analysis
and the surface scans.
Geordi...
as a child,
did you ever experience
a traumatic event?
You're wondering
about Timothy?
Yes.
I was caught
in a fire once.
I must have been...
I don't know--
about five, I guess.
It was before I got
the first visor,
and it was only
a couple of minutes
before my parents found me
and pulled me out.
And nobody got hurt,
but I tell you...
that was the longest
couple of minutes of my life.
It was a while
after that before
I could even let my parents
get out of earshot.
It was like...
I absolutely
needed to know
that they were there,
you know?
Timothy no longer has
that kind of support.
Yeah.
MAN:
"Dara and her brother
"found themselves
in the land of Tagas
"where the ruler,
Elamos the magnificent,
"had proclaimed as law:
"'no children
will be tolerated
within the great
kingdom.'
"When Dara saw
the proclamation,
"she just
laughed and said,
"'How magnificent
a ruler,
to be frightened
by the likes of us.'"
Timothy, we're done
with sculpture for now.
It's not finished.
We'll come back to it
next period.
Why don't you pick up
your mythology book
and follow along?
But it's not finished.
Magnetic residual
analysis confirms
that the Vico was
definitely attacked
inside the black cluster.
The graviton wave fronts
pushed the ship
to where we found it.
No signs of phaser burns
on the hull.
No, sir.
The torsional
stress levels point
to a disrupter-
style weapon.
Fracture points indicate
that the energy burst
came from a range of
less than 3,000 meters.
But that's a strategy
consistent with
a cloaked vessel--
Romulan or Klingon--
but we're quite
a distance
from either of
their territories.
The Breen have outposts
in this sector.
The attack on the Vico
is consistent with
their battle tactics
and their level of technology.
Thank you, Data.
But...
what would
the Breen be doing
inside the black cluster?
The boy described
a boarding party
with helmets
and phaser rifles.
A boarding party?
I don't think
that's likely, sir.
Counselor.
There was absolutely
no evidence
of anybody coming
on board the Vico.
We would have found
a transporter field trace.
Or if somebody had
used the entry ports,
we would have found
an electrostatic differential
in the docking latches,
and we didn't.
Could Timothy have
imagined that, Counselor?
Or could he be lying?
If he's lying, I haven't
been able to sense it.
Perhaps his emotional
trauma level is too high.
Why wouldn't
he tell us the truth?
He's still in shock.
It's hard to know
what's going on
in his mind right now.
Well, I'll go back and check
the sensor readings again,
but I don't think
we're gonna find anything.
Thank you, Geordi.
TROI:
Data?
Captain, I think
we should ask Data
to spend some time
with him.
I do not understand.
I'm very worried
about his behavior,
and what I just heard doesn't
make me feel any better.
Data, you're the only one
he's reached out to,
because
you rescued him.
We can use your relationship
with him to help his recovery.
Would Timothy be
more inclined
to tell Data the truth
about what happened?
It's a possibility.
Commander,
proceed with Timothy
as the counselor
suggests.
Aye, sir.
Counselor, exactly
how shall I proceed?
Just be with him.
You're a presence
he trusts,
and that's what
he needs most right now.
( door chime )
What?
Data.
Hello, Timothy.
May I enter?
Yeah.
Ahh.
You are attempting
to re-create...
the Dokkaran Temple
of Kural-Hanesh.
Isn't it great?
See, there's the big hallway
the teacher told us about.
And that's where
everybody came in.
That's where
they stood,
and that's where
the altar was.
What do you think?
Do you wish
a frank evaluation?
It lacks the harmony
that characterized
this particular temple
and the Dokkaran
culture in general.
You hate it.
No, I am not
capable of hatred.
I can't do
anything right.
You are making an
unwarranted extrapolation.
I was merely offering
an aesthetic analysis
of this
particular model.
The base appears
quite sturdy.
I told you.
May I suggest
a different approach?
You are attempting
to construct
the upper level before
the supports are in place.
Observe.
LA FORGE:
La Forge to Data.
Data here.
I need your help with
the shield modulators.
I will join you in a moment,
Geordi. Data out.
Lieutenant La Forge
requires my assistance.
Incredible.
Data?
How come you can
do that?
I am designed
to exceed human capacity,
both mentally
and physically.
Androids are
better than humans?
"Better" is a highly
subjective term.
I do not, for example,
possess the ability
to experience emotion,
as humans do.
No emotions?
You mean you can't
be happy or sad?
That is correct.
Why not?
My positronic brain
is not capable
of generating
those conditions.
Good-bye.
Data?
Can we build
something else later?
That would be
acceptable.
Bye.
( like Data: )
I am designed to exceed
human capacity.
That is correct.
The black cluster
was formed
almost nine billion years ago
when hundreds of
proto-stars
collapsed
in close proximity.
The resulting
gravitational forces
are both violent
and highly unpredictable.
To get anywhere
near the center,
we're going to have to push
through the graviton wave fronts
like the science ship
was designed to do.
I've already adjusted
our shields accordingly.
The gravitational forces
will affect sensor accuracy.
Detecting an enemy vessel
will be difficult.
Maybe that's what
happened to the Vico.
They didn't see anything coming
until it was too late.
Counselor,
has the boy volunteered
any further information?
No, but I do have
an appointment with him
in less than
half an hour.
If there's a possibility
of getting more from him,
I'd like you
to pursue it.
But we need to continue
our investigation.
We'll enter the black cluster
at 0700 hours tomorrow morning.
Dismissed.
Hello, Timothy.
Are you ready to go?
Yes, Counselor,
I am ready.
How are you feeling?
I am functioning within
established parameters.
Established parameters?
You sound like Data.
I am an android.
I see.
Well, let's go
for our walk, shall we?
That would be
acceptable.
TROI:
So, what would you like?
Androids do not need
to eat or drink.
However, we sometimes
like to taste things.
A tamarin frost,
please.
Would you like
anything, Counselor?
No, I'm fine,
thank you.
As you wish.
So... you're
no longer human.
I'm an android.
When did this happen?
I've always been
an android.
What's it like,
being an android?
I'm designed to exceed
human capacity,
both mentally
and physically,
but I do not
experience emotions.
You don't?
No emotion at all?
That is correct.
An android?
TROI:
I know it sounds unusual,
but it is
understandable.
Technically,
it's called enantiodromia.
Conversion into
the opposite.
Timothy went from
human to machine--
from being emotional
to being emotionless,
but the underlying
trauma is still there.
He's just found
a new way to suppress it.
Counselor...
how long will
this behavior last?
As long as
he needs it to.
Timothy is rebuilding
his identity as best he can.
The android persona is
just one step
along the way.
As soon as he feels stronger
and more sure of himself,
it should drop away
naturally.
I assume this is
not the time to confront him
about what happened
to his ship.
Not yet-- the best thing
we can do right now is
let Timothy take us
where he wants to go.
We should support the process
and even encourage it.
Data, I would like you
to make Timothy the best android
he can possibly be.
Timothy, your head movements
are counterproductive.
Can you be still?
But you do it.
The servo-mechanisms
in my neck are designed
to approximate
human movements.
I did not realize the effect
was so distracting.
I like it.
Data, are there any other
androids in Starfleet?
No, I am the only one.
How come
you're not captain?
My service record does not
yet warrant such a position.
Data?
What's the scariest thing
that ever happened to you?
Fear is not a quality
that I possess.
Because it's an emotion.
Correct.
But...
but what if you...
you had a nightmare?
I have never had
a nightmare.
I do not
require sleep.
Timothy...
are you having
disturbing dreams?
I do not
require sleep.
Is that satisfactory?
It's perfect.
Transfer circuits are
functioning properly.
Within established
parameters?
Absolutely.
Input processing,
pattern recognition,
all within
established parameters.
BOTH:
Thank you, Doctor.
I ran out of red ocher.
You may use mine.
Thank you.
Perhaps you should
return to your quarters.
I'm fine.
The servo-mechanisms
in my mouth
are designed to approximate
human movements.
That is not bad.
Thank you.
It is very...
expressive.
Thank you.
Is your painting
representative of something?
It's just a painting.
Timothy,
you understand
that you may speak to me
about anything you wish.
Any subject.
I understand.
At times...
I, too, find it
difficult
to share my thoughts
with others.
I am not always confident
that I am expressing myself
in a manner which
humans can comprehend.
But I do know that...
We are approaching
the perimeter.
I am picking up
the gravitational wave fronts.
Engage forward
shields 35%.
Shields up.
Drop to one-quarter
impulse, Ensign.
Yes, sir.
Bridge to Engineering.
Adjusting shield
frequencies now, Commander.
We'll have this smoothed out
in just a second.
Ensign, adjust course
for any deviations.
Yes, sir.
Resume
one-third impulse.
Captain, I am
reading something
at 400,000 kilometers
off the starboard bow--
possibly a ship.
Red alert.
Take us to visual range,
Ensign.
Adjusting course.
Sensor readings have
disappeared... wait.
I am picking up
another reading
at 400,000 kilometers
off the port bow.
It's gone... no...
It is back
to starboard.
Captain,
the black cluster's
distorting the sensors--
we're picking up
echoes of the Enterprise
reflecting off the wave fronts.
Cancel red alert.
Mr. Worf,
adjust sensors
to compensate
for the distortion.
Aye.
Sensor difficulties
have been reported
by ships traveling
through black clusters,
but never this extreme.
Captain,that formation
is seven times more massive
than any explored
previously.
That could explain
the difference.
Resume previous
course, Ensign.
Yes, sir.
He laughed.
Yes.
It's nice to see,
isn't it?
It is certainly
not consistent
with his android persona.
I'd say he's
beginning the process
of letting go
of that fantasy.
Then my work
with him is done.
No, I... I don't
think it is, Data.
A laugh is one step
in the right direction.
We need to help him
take a few more steps.
How, Counselor?
I'd like you
to talk to him
about your own
fascination with humanity.
If you explain
to Timothy
the appeal that
humanity has for you,
he might find it easier
to become a boy again.
This is great.
How is yours?
The complex
polysaccharides,
in reaction with
the carbon dioxide,
produces an unusual
combination of texture
and effervescence.
But how does
it taste?
Is it good?
I am not capable of tasting
in the manner you suggest.
However,
I can analyze
the composition
of a dessert
and make comparative
conclusions
about its possible effect
on the human palate.
But I neither like it
nor dislike it.
Oh.
I didn't realize that.
I have often wondered
what it must be like
to have one's...
mouth water
in anticipation
of the arrival
of a confection...
or to feel the pleasure
I have observed in humans
as they consume it.
You sound like you don't
want to be an android.
I am an android.
That will never change.
But if you
could change...
would you?
I have often wished
to be human.
I study people
carefully
in order to more closely
approximate human behavior.
Why? We're stronger
and smarter than humans.
We can do more
than they can.
But I cannot take pride
in my abilities.
I cannot take pleasure
in my accomplishments.
But we never have
to feel bad either.
I would gladly risk
feeling bad at times
if it also meant
that I could...
taste my dessert.
Captain, gravitational
wave front intensity
is increasing steadily--
1100 standard "G" units
and rising.
Let's see
if anyone's out there.
Mr. Worf,
attempt a wide-range
sensor sweep.
Aye, sir.
Gravitational distortion
is too great, Captain.
The scanning signal
is again being
reflected off
the wave fronts.
I am unable
to compensate.
Sensors are useless.
Mr. Data to
the bridge, please.
DATA:
Acknowledged.
Adjust sensors
to short range.
Attempt a limited
positron scan.
The distortion is
still in effect.
Try to jacket
the scanning beam.
The secondary beam is
being distorted as well.
Mr. Data,
our sensors are being
rendered ineffective
by the field
distortion.
I want your analysis.
Mr. Worf...
fire phasers,
maximum intensity,
limited spectrum,
001-mark-045.
An experiment,
Captain?
Exactly,
Number One.
Firing phasers.
Explanation,
Mr. Data?
Phaser energy
was reflected
by the gravitational
wave fronts.
It is similar
to the phenomenon
distorting our
sensor signals.
Phasers and sensors,
both useless.
Mr. Data, this
reflection phenomenon--
would it have
the same effect
on a disrupter-style
weapon?
Yes, sir, disrupters
would be ineffective.
And a ship's
cloaking field?
It would be extremely
difficult to maintain, sir.
Mr. Data,
is it at all likely
that the Vico could
have been attacked
inside the cluster?
Given the effects
we have observed,
the probability is
exceedingly remote, sir.
Picard to Counselor Troi.
TROI:
Yes, Captain?
Counselor, will you bring
Timothy to my ready room?
Timothy,
can you tell us
what happened
to your ship?
I did tell you!
Tell us again.
We were attacked.
That is highly unlikely.
Our investigations...
We were attacked!
Timothy...
androids do not lie.
It was me.
Please explain.
I did it.
I killed them all.
Everything was shaking.
I lost my balance.
I was just trying
to hold on to something.
I didn't mean
to do it.
What was it that you
didn't mean to do, Timothy?
My arm...
hit the computer panel.
That's what destroyed
the ship.
The ship was damaged
when your arm hit
the computer panel?
Timothy,
listen to me.
The damage to your ship
might have occurred
at the same time
your arm touched the panel,
but it was only
a coincidence.
This wasn't your fault.
Yes, it was.
It is not possible.
The onboard
control systems
for every starship require
a user code clearance.
You could not have
inadvertently affected
any of the Vico's systems.
Your computer had
safety precautions.
There is nothing
you could have touched
that would have
damaged your ship.
You're not responsible
for what happened
to your parents, Timothy.
But if it wasn't me...
We're trying to determine
what happened right now,
and if there is anything
you can remember that
might assist...
That's just how it was...
when it started
on the Vico.
Wave front intensity
has increased.
Increase shields
to 75%.
Aye, sir.
Damage, Mr. Worf?
Minimal, sir.
Shields are holding.
Ensign, full about.
Go to warp two.
The gravitational
distortion is too high.
We can't maintain
a warp field.
Full shields.
WORF:
Aye.
Captain, impulse power
has been disrupted.
The helm won't respond.
We couldn't get out
either.
Timothy, perhaps
you and I should go below
and get out
of everyone's way.
No.
RIKER:
Riker to La Forge.
Can you get me
more power
to the shields?
Stand by.
That's what
they kept saying.
"More shields.
More shields."
Timothy,
accompany me, please.
I want you to recall everything
you heard people say
aboard the Vico
before it was destroyed.
I don't know.
Just that.
Just "more shields."
LA FORGE:
Captain, I've transferred
fusion reactors
four through nine
into the shield array.
That should double
the shield strength.
Wave front intensity
has increased
by an order
of magnitude.
Impact in three...
two... one.
Wave front intensity is
continuing to increase.
Structural overpressure
now exceeding 180%.
La Forge!
I don't understand.
That should have
been enough.
We could run
the shield grid
directly off the warp drive.
Go ahead, Commander.
Initiating warp
transfer pathways...
now.
LA FORGE:
Diverting warp power
to the shields.
"Warp power
to the shields."
They said that too,
Data, I'm positive.
Wave front intensity
has increased
by a factor of ten.
Contact in 31 seconds.
Without additional
power to the shields,
the outer hull
will not hold.
La Forge?
Warp transfer
to the shields complete.
That's as strong as
they're going to get.
WORF:
Impact in 15 seconds.
Sir, drop the shields.
That's suicide,
Data.
Captain,
drop the shields.
Make it so.
Aye.
Our own shields
caused the increases
in the wave fronts, sir.
We have been
experiencing
a harmonic
amplification effect.
The more energy
we dumped into the shield,
the worse the impact.
Precisely.
That is also
what destroyed the Vico.
When Timothy remembered
similar procedures on his ship,
I initiated an analysis
of shield output
to wave front
amplification
and discovered
a correlation.
If we had transferred
all that warp power
to the shields...
it would have torn
the ship apart.
Status, Ensign.
Navigation is
coming back online.
Full about.
One quarter impulse.
Take us out of here.
TEACHER / CHILDREN:
♪ Row, row, row your boat ♪
♪ Gently down
the stream ♪
♪ Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily ♪
♪ Life is
but a dream ♪
♪ Row, row,
row your boat ♪
♪ Gently down
the stream ♪
♪ Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily ♪
Timothy's a boy feeling
a great deal of pain,
but he is
a boy again.
Is this difficult
for you, Data?
Difficult?
To watch him moving away
from being like you.
That would require
an emotional context
which I cannot provide.
Okay, everybody,
let's go.
Hello, Timothy.
Hi, Data.
How are you?
I am operating within
established parameters.
How are you?
I miss my parents.
But...
I'm okay.
I guess you thought
I was pretty silly
when I had my hair
like yours and everything.
I have been told
that imitation is
the highest form
of flattery.
Can we still
do things together,
even if I'm not
really an android?
I have many
human friends.
I would be pleased
to count you among them.
That would be...
acceptable.