Captain's Log,
Stardate 45429.3.
While on a mapping survey,
we are conveying
a delegation of
Ullians to Kaldra IV.
These telepathic historians
conduct their research
by retrieving
long-forgotten memories.
It's a chipped cup, off-white...
with a crack in it.
I can see it, but I don't
remember anything else about it.
MAN: When you see it,
do you hear any sounds?
No, I don't think so.
Wait.
Yes, uh... humming.
Someone's humming.
A woman.
Yes, but I don't
know who it is.
Try to touch the cup.
Ooh, it-- it has a sharp
edge where it's chipped.
Is there anything
inside the cup?
A liquid... dark.
MAN:
Like tea?
It's not hot.
It's bitter.
There's something else
inside the cup.
Yes, a... a wooden handle.
MAN:
A spoon?
No, it's more delicate
than that.
MAN:
Reach out for it.
A brush.
An ink brush.
( humming )
I hear that humming again.
Keep listening to it,
and hold out the brush.
See if anyone
takes it from you.
( woman humming )
( woman speaking in
foreign language)
It's Obachan...
my grandmother.
She's doing
ink brush writing.
I can remember it now.
She, uh... she used that cup
for cleaning the brushes
and it was my job to
fill the cup with water
and bring it
to the table.
I would sit beside
her and watch
the most beautiful
characters come from that brush
and the whole time, she'd be
humming to herself.
I-- I remember it
like it was yesterday.
That is remarkable.
You remembered
such vivid details.
For years, I've seen that
old cup in my memory,
but I could never
remember what it was
or why it was important.
Thank you.
Well, you're entirely welcome,
young lady.
Perhaps someone else
would care to try?
You, madam?
You're thinking about that
first childhood kiss.
Would you like to
remember more about it?
Father, you know you're
not supposed to probe
someone's memory unless
they've given you permission.
You are right.
But sometimes,
with a beautiful woman,
I cannot help myself.
( laughing )
How about you, Commander?
Got any memories
you feel like digging up?
None that I'd care to
share with an audience.
It's getting late.
I'd better be going.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
It is perplexing to me
that the Ullians' ability
to retrieve memory
is so highly prized.
If an event were important
enough to be recovered,
why would it
have been forgotten?
Well, it's not quite the same
for us as it is for you, Data.
You record every second of
every moment of your life.
That is correct.
And then, if you
want to recall
any one of those moments,
you just access the
proper memory circuit.
My understanding of
the human brain
suggests the process
is the same for you.
Each memory is encoded
in chains of molecules.
If you want to
retrieve it,
you simply access the
proper RNA sequence.
Yeah, that's true.
Then in what way
is it different?
Sometimes
there are memories
we just can't...
( snaps )
...access at the
spur of the moment.
For instance,
I have no recollection
of how I spent my
last birthday.
Birthdays are
important occasions,
and you would think that I'd
remember how I spent the day,
but right now, I can't even
remember... where I was.
Deck two.
On the other hand,
I remember everything
about the time I got my
first pet-- a Circassian cat.
I was eight.
I remember how
funny-looking he was.
excited I was.
It was as if it
happened yesterday.
Perhaps you remember the
pleasant memories
and forget the
unpleasant ones.
No, sometimes the bad memories
can be the most intense of all.
It would seem there is
no predictable pattern
to human memory.
It would seem.
This library of ours has been in
the planning stages for years--
a collection of the
retrieved memories
of races from many
different star systems--
What my son means to say
is we think of ourselves
as archaeologists
of the mind.
We believe that the history
of a world is contained
in the personal
experience of its people.
Rather like the ancient
oral historians on Earth.
Exactly.
The library we propose
will be a vast storehouse
of these individual memories.
That sounds like
quite a project.
How long will it take to
finish your studies on Kaldra?
Many months.
We've been working
for years,
and we've surveyed
only 11 planets
in eight star systems.
But it's our
way of life.
We wouldn't want to
do anything else.
Captain, Mr. Tarmin
gave us a demonstration
of his abilities
this afternoon.
It's fascinating.
Perhaps you would like
to resurrect some memories?
TARMIN: I'd be happy to probe
your recollections, Captain.
Most people find it
an enjoyable experience.
I'm sure.
However, I don't think
I would make
a particularly good subject.
I'm sure you'd be ideal,
and you must have
some intriguing memories.
TARMIN: We won't be on
your ship for long.
This may be your last chance.
( chuckling )
Yes, well...
Tarmin, we mustn't
influence people.
We must let them
come to us willingly.
I have found over the years
there are many
who want the experience
of memory retrieval,
but who lack some
encouragement
in order
to come forward.
You, Mr. Worf.
I would love to explore
Klingon memories.
Klingons do not allow
themselves to be probed.
But there is nothing to fear.
Father...
I am not fearful.
Commander La Forge? You?
I don't think so.
Thanks, anyway.
( chuckles )
I have rarely encountered
such squeamish people.
Dr. Crusher?
Commander Riker?
Mr. Tarmin, are all Ullians
able to read memories?
Oh, no, my dear.
The technique requires
special training.
It is a serious commitment.
INAD: It takes
years of study.
Tarmin is the most
proficient of our group.
Once, Jev spent two days
with a contingent
of elderly Gentons.
He couldn't get anything
from them.
I spent only one hour
with them and retrieved
a fragment from the
Gentonian trade wars.
Excuse me.
( door opens, closes )
Exactly how long
will it be
before we get to Kaldra,
Captain?
PICARD:
Mr. Data?
DATA:
Four days, 11 hours.
Jev?
I'm sorry, I--
I'm being rude.
No, not at all.
My father finds it amusing
to demean me in public.
I reach the point where I
don't wanna hear any more.
It's not easy having
an overbearing parent.
Believe me,
I know how you feel.
Oh, that's right--
you're an empath.
Oh, I can't read Ullians.
But I do know a
certain Betazoid mother
who is a great deal
like your father.
Deck eight.
Deck 16.
I've learned to remind myself
that my mother and I
are two separate
individuals.
Mm-hmm... and have you
enjoyed much success
with this approach,
Counselor?
No... but I do keep
reminding myself.
( laughs )
Good night.
Good night,
Counselor, and...
and thank you.
RIKER: Have you stopped
thinking about us?
Hot chocolate.
( gasps )
Imzadi, we can't--
not when we're serving
on the same ship.
Have you stopped
thinking about us?
Just answer that.
I can't stop
thinking about you.
Will, don't.
Imzadi, we can't--
not when we're serving
on the same ship.
Have you stopped
thinking about us?
We mustn't do this.
Will, don't!
Will...
no!
( gasps )
Imzadi...
RIKER: Have you stopped
thinking about us?
Just answer that.
No! No!
Don't! Don't!
I can't stop
thinking about you.
Imzadi.
Have you stopped
thinking about us?
( echoing )
No!
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45430.9.
Counselor Troi
has fallen into a deep coma.
After thorough examination,
Dr. Crusher
has been unable to find
signs of illness or infection.
Any change,
Dr. Martin?
No, I'm still getting unusual
neural transmitter readings
in the diencephalon.
But they might be a
result of the coma.
Can you bring her
out of it?
I've tried standard
revival techniques.
She doesn't respond.
Until I find out
what's caused this,
I don't want to try anything
more extreme.
Do you know what she was
doing when this happened?
No. She was found in
her quarters this morning
when she didn't show up
for an appointment.
She was dressed for bed, but
the bed hadn't been slept in.
Who was the last person
to speak with her?
She left the dinner last night
with one of the Ullians.
I'll talk to him.
Ask if they would consent
to an examination,
just to be certain.
Mmm.
I'll check
the bio-filter readings
from the Ullian transporter log.
It's possible they could still
be carrying a harmful organism.
May I join you?
Commander...
of course.
Something's wrong?
Counselor Troi is ill.
I'm sorry to hear it.
She's more than ill,
she's in a coma.
Dr. Crusher doesn't
know what's causing it
or how to treat her.
When did this happen?
Apparently
sometime last night.
That's why I wanted
to talk to you.
You may have been the
last person to see her.
Did you go with her
into her quarters?
Are you suggesting that I
behaved improperly, Commander?
Not at all.
I'm just trying
to trace her steps.
We talked...
in a turbolift briefly.
She got out at deck eight.
I did not go with her.
Jev, I'm not accusing
you of anything.
Did she mention
feeling ill?
She seemed fine.
She has a wonderful
sense of humor.
If you have no objections,
Dr. Crusher would like to
examine you and your group.
To what end?
She's just trying to eliminate
the possibility that one of you
might be a carrying an organism
that was harmful
to Deanna.
I'm not implying that you
did anything intentional.
I'm just trying to get to
the bottom of the mystery.
We have nothing to hide.
If you wish to spend
time examining us--
Fine, thank you.
Deanna...
I don't know if
you can hear me.
I've-- I've heard doctors say
that even when someone's
in a coma,
they may be able to hear
when people talk to them...
that it might help stimulate
the brain, speed healing.
In fact, I think you
did that for me once,
when I was in pretty bad shape.
I just thought...
it might help to
hear a friendly voice...
even if you don't know
you're hearing it.
We've been busy
mapping the sector.
It's been pretty routine.
The most unusual thing we've
seen is a binary star system.
Let's see,
what else?
I've finished the personnel
review that we were working on.
You can check it out...
when you wake up.
I miss you.
Please, don't stay away
too long.
Will...
Will, I promise
I'll let you know
the minute she regains
consciousness.
I know.
There's nothing
you can do here.
You'll wear
yourself out.
All right.
It's late.
Go to bed.
That's an order.
( alarm sounding )
MAN:
Keller is still in there!
RIKER:
Let's move it!
Out! Out! Out!
Let's go!
Everybody move!
Out! Out!
Come on! Keep moving!
LA FORGE:
Commander!
I need to bring
that door down.
COMPUTER:
Evacuate immediately.
Keller, can you
get to a Jefferies tube?
Ensign Keller, answer me!
You killed her.
Keller is still in there!
Commander, radiation
levels are critical.
We've got to
seal it off.
She was right
behind me.
Bring down the door.
Keep moving!
LA FORGE: Commander!
I need to bring
that door down.
Out! Out! Let's go.
Keller is still
in there!
Keller is
still in there.
Riker to
Transporter Room Three.
Prepare to beam Ensign Keller
out of the engine room.
( alarm sounding )
Keller is still
in there.
Keller is still in there!
You killed her.
Ensign Keller,
answer me.
You killed her.
I've got to get that
isolation door down.
Keller is still in there!
Bring down the door!
You killed her!
I need that door down!
( echoed overlapping shouting )
Bridge to Commander Riker.
Picard to Commander Riker.
Answer, please.
Computer,
locate Commander Riker.
COMPUTER: Commander Riker
is in his quarters.
On my way, sir.
DR. CRUSHER:
Medical Log, Stardate 45431.7.
Commander Riker
is the second officer
who has fallen into an
unexplained coma.
I have examined the Ullians,
and ruled out the possibility
that they carry
a harmful organism.
I compared Deanna's
brain scan to the one
that I took during
her last physical.
There is a difference.
This time, there's a trace
of electropathic activity.
And Commander Riker?
I found the same pattern.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say they both had
Iresine Syndrome.
That's the only
medical condition
that would produce
that pattern.
What is Iresine Syndrome?
A very rare
neurological disorder
first diagnosed in
the 23rd century.
It's characterized by an
identical electropathic residue.
Why discount the possibility
that it's responsible
for these comas?
Iresine is always accompanied
by a severely decreased
histamine count.
Both Will and Deanna
showed normal levels.
I've asked
Commander La Forge
to conduct a shipwide
diagnostic
to determine any other agent
that might cause
the same
electropathic pattern.
Commander Riker and
Counselor Troi
were in perfect health
until the Ullians arrived.
It would be wise to quarantine
the aliens.
I believe that
it would be premature
to take that action, Mr. Worf.
There's no real evidence
linking these comas
with the Ullians.
That's true, but there
is something curious.
The electropathic residue
I discovered
is located in the thalamus.
That's the area
of the cerebral cortex
that involves memory function.
I've been accused
of putting people to sleep
with one too many
stories, Captain.
But this is the first time
it's ever been suggested
that I might be the
cause of someone's coma.
I mean no disrespect,
but we are faced
with an alarming situation.
Why do you suspect us,
Captain?
Suspect is perhaps
too strong a word.
I'm simply trying to
determine what has caused
two of my officers to
fall into comas.
But you've already
examined us.
We aren't carrying
anything harmful.
BEVERLY: In further
study of the victims,
I detected some
abnormal patterns
in the area of the brain
that involves memory.
In the light of your
telepathic abilities,
it raises the question.
Captain, it is not our
wish to obstruct you.
What would you like?
If I could do some further
examinations tomorrow--
perhaps monitor you
during a memory probe.
Scrutiny does not frighten us.
We will be happy
to cooperate, Doctor.
Thank you.
I'll contact you
in the morning.
Since you're
the only person on board
to undergo a memory probe
by the Ullians,
I'd like to do
a neurological work-up
and see if I can detect
any residual effect.
Dr. Martin will
monitor your vital signs
while I conduct the scan.
I'm happy to help.
Have you noticed
any unusual symptoms
since the probe?
Headaches,
dizziness?
No, nothing like that.
It was a wonderful
experience.
Electrical activity
is normal.
C.P.K. levels are normal.
Hippocampus is stable...
and the thalamus...
The thalamus is normal.
There is no indication at all
of any electropathic residual.
Is that good?
Oh, you're fine, Keiko.
But I am no closer to
solving this mystery.
Computer, locate
the electropathic pattern
described in medical database
four-delta-one.
COMPUTER:
Electropathic pattern located.
Okay, we're going to track down
any possible cause
of that brain pattern.
First, what are the medical
conditions
that might account for it?
COMPUTER:
Iresine Syndrome is a cause
of the electropathic pattern.
Right, and Dr. Crusher
already eliminated that.
So, how many non-medical
forces or substances
might cause the pattern?
COMPUTER:
There are 22 non-medical agents.
Okay, and how many of those
are present on the Enterprise?
COMPUTER: None are present
on the Enterprise.
Are the ship's
sensors calibrated
to detect all those agents?
COMPUTER: All agents are
scanned by the sensors.
Okay. Let's start
with the chemical substances.
Name them.
COMPUTER: Ferrazene,
hylanatine, dardilion,
chrysimite, and manzene.
Hmm.
Ferrazene has a complex
molecular structure.
It breaks down
into bilenium and tarrisite.
Do the sensors scan for those?
COMPUTER: Ship's sensors
scan for both compounds.
And are they present
on the Enterprise?
COMPUTER: Bilenium and
tarrisite are not present.
Do any of the substances
break down into by-products
that are not scanned for?
COMPUTER: Dardilion contains
the by-product nilizene.
Sensors do not routinely
scan for that substance.
Well, this isn't
a routine situation.
Scan for the nilizene.
COMUTER: There is no nilizene
on the Enterprise.
How did I know
you were gonna say that?
Okay, let's move on to the
non-chemical agents.
Anything more
I can do for you?
No, thanks.
I was just doing some reading
on the Iresine Syndrome.
If a new strain has developed,
that might explain
the normal histamine counts.
Any luck?
Not so far.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow.
PICARD: You shouldn't
remember him like this.
You don't have to do this.
It's important to me.
I have to see him.
It's good of you
to come.
It's the least
I can do.
PICARD: You shouldn't
remember him like this.
BEVERLY: I have to face
the fact that he's gone.
You shouldn't
remember him like this.
It's good of you
to come with me.
It's the least I can do.
You shouldn't
remember him like this.
( Jev's voice: )
It's the least I can do.
( gasps )
( screaming )
I've spent two hours
having a cozy little
chat with the computer.
I've checked everything
I could think of--
any possible agent
that might cause
that electropathic pattern.
I assume from your tone of
voice you were unsuccessful.
Didn't find a thing.
Dr. Crusher's not gonna
be too happy with...
Emergency medical team
to Dr. Crusher's
office immediately.
Dr. Crusher had me working
on a shipwide diagnostic.
I'd gone to give her
the results when I found her.
Did your scans provide any
insights into these comas?
None. I've checked
and cross-checked.
They're just dead ends.
We seem to have eliminated all
of the known factors
which may have
caused the comas,
except for the Ullians.
Mr. Data, I want you
to investigate
those 11 planets
that the Ullians visited.
See if there were any reports
of unexplained comas.
Aye, sir.
In the meantime,
we must consider
restricting them
to their quarters
as a precautionary measure.
If one of them
is behind this,
will keeping telepaths
in their quarters
prevent it from
happening again?
What else can we do?
Station a guard?
Set up a force field?
I don't see that those will
be any more effective.
DR. MARTIN:
Sick Bay to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
DR. MARTIN: Counselor Troi
has regained consciousness.
She's asked for you, sir.
I'm on my way.
It's like waking up
from a nightmare,
and not remembering
what it was about.
What is the last thing
you do remember?
My hair.
I was brushing my hair.
And then?
( sighs )
I don't know.
Just waking up here.
Why do I feel so frightened?
What happened to me?
We were hoping
that you could tell us.
How long have I been here?
Three days.
Three days?
You were the first.
The next day, Commander Riker
fell into a similar coma.
Last night,
Dr. Crusher.
What is going on here?
We're not certain.
It may be that there
is some unusual effect
produced by the Ullians'
telepathic activity.
I'm gonna talk to them.
And in the meantime,
you are to stay here
and recuperate.
But if you remember anything
at all about what happened,
I want you to
tell me immediately.
What are you suggesting,
Captain?
That you voluntarily confine
yourself to your quarters,
at least until we have
unravelled this mystery.
We're to be prisoners?
Father.
PICARD: No, please,
don't look on it like that.
We have done
everything we can
to explain these comas.
We have performed
physical examinations,
neurological scans.
We have conducted
a shipwide diagnostic
looking for viruses,
parasites, infestations.
We have investigated every
possible cause we could imagine,
and we have found nothing--
nothing to explain
these comas.
The only variable that we have
not been able to eliminate
is your presence
here on this ship.
Now, in the light
of our actions,
we would ask you to understand
my request and to agree to it.
Captain, our history indicates
that we do not adversely affect
the people we contact.
I know that.
Then... are you implying
an intentional assault?
I'm simply considering
all possibilities.
Surely, you would
give us the chance
to prove that we're innocent?
If that's possible,
of course.
Well, then I would propose
doing a memory probe
of Counselor Troi.
You have said
that she doesn't remember
anything that happened
before she lapsed
into unconsciousness.
I could retrieve that memory.
There is a possibility that
it could explain the coma
and prove our innocence.
I'm sorry, I couldn't possibly
subject Counselor Troi
to a potentially
dangerous procedure.
And I refuse to be a party
to any of these proceedings.
Jev is making a reasonable
request, Captain.
If we're to be accused,
surely, we're entitled
to a defense.
Tarmin did a memory
probe on another
of your crew.
Has she suffered
any ill effects?
No.
And neither will
Counselor Troi.
Please.
You may have as many
people there as you need
to guarantee her safety.
But give us this chance
to vindicate ourselves.
I will discuss the matter
with Counselor Troi.
Well, that's it
for Melina II.
No unexplained comas
during the time
the Ullians
were working there.
We have yet to
receive transmission
from the two planets
of the Nel system.
Perhaps they will
show different results.
Maybe...
and maybe we're not checking
for the right thing.
Please clarify.
We haven't looked into the
comas that were explained.
Why would we do that?
Well, remember what
Dr. Crusher said
right after Counselor Troi
became unconscious--
that it looked exactly
like Iresine Syndrome,
except for the
histamine count?
Yes.
Well, maybe not
every medical facility
is as careful as Dr. Crusher.
Maybe it's easier to
just make a quick diagnosis
rather than keep hunting
for the real cause.
You are searching for instances
of Iresine Syndrome.
Right...
And correlating them
with the visits by
the Ullians and...
And there we are.
Two cases of
Iresine Syndrome
on Hurada III,
at exactly the time Tarmin
and his group were there.
Let's check
the other planets.
I think we may have
something here.
Counselor,
I want to reiterate.
If you have any
doubts whatsoever
about this procedure, you don't
have to go through with it.
I want to do it, Captain.
Something awful
happened to me,
and I don't even
know what it was.
Very well.
Counselor, what's the
last thing you remember
about the other night?
Brushing my hair.
Would you get
your hairbrush?
Tell me about
brushing your hair.
Do you do it
every night?
Yes, when I'm ready
for bed.
What is it?
Someone's touching my hair.
Someone's with you
in the room?
No.
No, I'm alone.
There's no one there.
Go on.
I get some hot chocolate.
Something's happening.
I'm alone in my quarters.
I'm remembering something
from a few years ago.
Go back into
that memory.
You said... someone
was touching your hair?
Yes... and...
it's Will Riker.
That's right.
I was thinking of him.
Remembering a time when
you were with him.
Yes, after a poker game.
It's a pleasant memory.
Stay with it.
( gasping )
Now, he's hurting me.
You're... you're frightened.
I want him to stop.
( sobbing )
( gasps )
It's not Will.
Somebody's taken
his place.
Someone else is there,
who is it?
( crying )
No...
he shouldn't be here.
Why is he here?
Stop.
You're hurting me.
Can you see his face?
Yes.
( sobbing )
Imzadi...
No! Stop!
You're hurting me!
Who is it?
Who is doing this to you?
( gasps )
It's Tarmin.
It's your father.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45433.2.
We have set a course
for Starbase 440
where the Ullians
will disembark
and return home.
Inad and I have contacted
our home planet.
If you want to
prosecute my father,
the authorities there
will support you.
I'm not sure we have any legal
basis for such a prosecution.
Memory invasion
is simply not a crime
that we've ever had
to contend with.
According to what I've
just learned, it's a practice
that was abolished on our world
centuries ago.
What could motivate
someone like your father
to commit such an act?
I don't know.
A perverse source
of pleasure, perhaps.
A way to exercise control
over another.
Your father claims,
quite strenuously,
that he's innocent.
( chuckles )
My father has never been one
to admit that he's wrong.
But it is difficult to believe
he'd be capable of this.
I am told that the punishment
for this crime is quite severe.
We are monitoring my father's
telepathic activities.
You have my assurance
he won't assault
anyone else.
I am sorry for this, Captain.
Picard to Commander Data.
DATA: Yes, Captain?
How's your search coming?
We have uncovered
several cases, sir,
but have not yet completed
our investigation.
We'll inform the medical
personnel on those planets
that we have discovered the
true nature of the comas.
I'm sure they'll appreciate
knowing what really happened.
Yes, sir. We will
keep searching, sir.
We just got the transmission
from the Nel system, Data.
No mention of
Iresine Syndrome,
but there are two
unexplained comas
on one planet,
none on the other.
And were the
Ullians present?
Checking the mission logs.
That's funny.
On stardates
45321 and 45323,
when the comas occurred,
Tarmin was on
his home planet.
He wasn't anywhere
near the Nel system.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Jev.
We'll be reaching
starbase soon.
I wanted to say good-bye
and to apologize
again for my father.
There's no need.
You're not responsible
for what he did.
Before all this
happened, I...
I had hoped we
might become friends.
We still can.
After what he's
put you through?
Maybe you can forget.
I'm not sure I can.
You're so lovely.
I have to go.
Good-bye.
Jev... you're upset.
Would you like to talk?
No.
You'd feel better
if you did.
Why do you have
to be so nice?
So... so lovely.
What... what's happening?
It's happening again.
You're so beautiful...
so fragile.
It was you.
It was always you.
Have you stopped
thinking about us?
No!
( whimpering )
No..
No! No!
Don't! Don't!
I won't let you.
No!
( screams )
DATA:
Counselor...
are you all right?
Yes.
Why are you here?
How did you know?
We discovered two instances
of unexplained coma
on Nel Three while
the Ullians were there,
but Tarmin was not
part of the group.
Further examination
revealed
that there was only
one Ullian present
for all incidents
of coma-- Jev.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45435.8.
Dr. Crusher and Commander Riker
regained consciousness
while we were en route
to the Ullian home world.
The slow process
of their recovery has begun.
I have asked that the finest
physicians on my world
meet with you all
upon our return, to help you
in your healing process.
They've been in contact
with us already.
Thank you.
It's been three centuries
since we treated
anyone for this...
this form of rape.
But there are medical
records from that era.
It was a time of great
violence for my people--
a time we thought we had
put far behind us.
That this could happen now...
is unimaginable.
Earth was once
a violent planet too.
At times, the chaos threatened
the very fabric of life.
But like you, we evolved.
We found better ways to
handle our conflicts.
But I think no one can deny
that the seed of violence
remains within each of us.
We must recognize that,
because that violence
is capable of
consuming each of us,
as it consumed your son.