Captain's Log,
Stardate 45470.1:
The Enterprise has been
diverted to the Moab sector
to track
a stellar core fragment
of a disintegrated
neutron star.
Our science teams
have been asked to monitor
the planetary disruptions
it may cause.
We've got a problem.
Our core fragment is going to
pass by Moab IV in six days.
Isn't that exactly
what we anticipated?
We didn't anticipate there
would be someone living there.
An artificial environment
has been constructed
on the southern
continent, sir.
You've definitely
established
that there is
someone inside it?
Yes, Captain, sensors are
reading human life-forms.
Human?
Are they responding
to our hails, Mr. Worf?
Negative, sir.
Any starships reported missing
in this sector, Mr. Data?
No, sir.
How the hell did they find
themselves on a deserted planet?
LA FORGE: I'm pretty sure
they know we're here.
Mr. La Forge?
Our sensors are picking up
deep E-M readings.
Looks like wave patterns from
an obsolete subspace relay.
Which would suggest
they also have the ability
to communicate with us.
Mr. Worf, open the lower
band frequencies
most commonly used
in the last century.
Channel open.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation starship
Enterprise.
It is urgent
that you respond.
Sir, the defensive shield
around the structure
is increasing strength.
Not exactly
a welcome mat.
We mean you no harm.
We must warn you
that your planet
is about to experience
massive seismic disruptions
due to an approaching
stellar core fragment.
No structure will be able
to withstand them.
They are responding.
PICARD:
On screen.
Enterprise,
I am Aaron Conor.
PICARD:
Mr. Conor, we were unaware
that there were human colonies
in this system.
I don't want to be rude,
Captain,
but we don't wish
to interact with outsiders.
I'm only responding
because of your warning.
The fragment will have
serious effects
on your planet
within six days.
Yes, I know.
We have been tracking it.
But our biosphere
is constructed
to withstand quakes of 8.7
on the Richter scale.
Mr. Data?
The fragment has a density
of 100 billion kilograms
per cubic centimeter.
As a result,
when it passes Moab IV,
it will cause
tectonic shifts
well beyond 8.7
on the Richter scale.
I'm afraid we are going to have
to evacuate your people.
Evacuate?
That is not possible.
There must be an alternative.
Well, we will
gladly explore
the possibility of it
with you Mr. Conor.
Would you like to
come aboard to discuss it?
Our environment is sealed.
No one can get in or out.
We are capable of
matter/energy transport.
Matter/energy?
We can take you directly
through the structure.
Really?
That's quite remarkable.
May we arrange
for your transport?
No. I must remain here.
But under the circumstances,
I will permit
a small delegation
from your ship
inside the biosphere,
if only to see this
matter/energy transportation
you speak of.
PICARD: Very good.
Commander Riker and an away team
will be with you shortly.
Picard out.
This is a mistake, Aaron.
Good Lord, Martin,
what would you have me do?
Anything that would
keep them out of here.
We have nothing to hide.
We have a great deal
to lose.
What is that?
It's them.
Look at this, Martin.
Incredible.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
TROI:
It's lovely.
I can understand why you're
reluctant to leave, Mr. Conor.
Not just reluctant,
Ms. Troi,
it is imperative
that we remain.
It would be suicide
to evacuate.
It would destroy
everything we have worked
for two centuries
to accomplish.
You see this is
an engineered society.
Engineered?
Genetically engineered.
Our ancestors came from Earth
to create a perfect society.
They believed that through
controlled procreation,
they could create
people without flaws
and those people
would build a paradise.
All of you have been
selectively bred?
Your DNA patterns chosen?
Eight generations of us.
We have immeasurably extended
the potential of humanity--
physically, psychologically.
We have evolved beyond...
beyond...
beyond us.
Frankly, yes.
No one in this society
would be blind, for example.
No offense intended.
I can see you just fine, sir.
Yes, well,
my point was just...
Thank you, Martin.
Perhaps you've also
made it clear
there are still
a few imperfections
we're working on.
For the most part,
we have achieved
a fully integrated existence,
not just among ourselves,
but with our environment.
We don't just live here,
we're a part of our environment.
It is part of us.
Every plant life,
every microscopic life-form
is a part
of the master design.
We cannot separate
ourselves from it
without irreparably altering
who and what we are.
Your presence here
has already begun to affect
the entire balance
of our society.
If we don't survive,
the balance
of our society
won't mean a great deal,
will it?
I apologize,
but he is performing
his function
as he is designed to do.
LA FORGE:
And what function might that be?
CONOR: He is the interpreter
of our founders' intentions
for the society.
A judge.
Yes. More or less.
Obviously, he has
no diplomatic talents.
And obviously,
you do.
CONOR:
I have been bred to fill
this specific role.
We grow up knowing exactly
what our society needs from us,
what we are expected to do.
RIKER: That must take some
of the fun out of it.
Not at all.
My entire
psychological makeup
tells me that
I was born to lead.
I am exactly what
I would choose to be.
Think of it another way.
Are there still people
in your society
who have not yet discovered
who they really are
or what they were meant
to do with their lives?
They may be
in the wrong job.
They may be writing
bad poetry.
Or worse yet,
they may be great poets
working as laborers,
never to be discovered.
That does not happen here.
It is, for us,
an ideal existence
and we will not
give it up easily.
We will do whatever we can
to help you preserve it.
Hannah, I'd like you
to meet our guests.
Oh, yes, of course,
from the starship.
I've been looking forward
to speaking with you.
CONOR:
Hannah Bates is
one of our scientists.
If there's any way
to sure up our defenses,
Hannah will find it.
She has a remarkable talent
in theoretical physics.
I've worked up
a few schematics
based on
gravimetric potentials
and deflector
energy allocation.
Geordi, Troi, and I will
return to the Enterprise.
When you've reached a
conclusion, you can contact us.
Commander,
if Mr. Conor doesn't mind,
I'd like to stay and see
more of his colony.
No, no.
That would be fine.
I'd like you to see it.
Riker to Enterprise.
One to beam up.
ENSIGN:
Acknowledged, Commander.
Energize.
Are you sure my being here
is not going to be...
disruptive?
Disruptive?
You mean what
Martin was saying?
Well, I certainly
wouldn't wish
to throw off
your entire balance.
Too late.
The damage is done.
Seriously.
I sometimes think that
strict interpreters like Martin
have forgotten
we're still human.
We'll adjust,
accommodate.
There must be other
unexpected events
you have to deal with--
an untimely death,
an accident.
Our geneticists
are able to screen out
any congenital health risks
before conception.
Our population
is diverse enough
to maintain
a genetic balance
in the event
of accidental death,
but very little that is
unexpected occurs here.
Am I making this sound
incredibly dull?
Not at all.
I'll tell you the truth,
but I'll deny it
if you tell Martin.
I found today exhilarating...
meeting you,
meeting new people
with new ideas.
I feel the same
about being here.
I'm something of
a student of human nature
and I find this all
fascinating.
A student of human nature?
I'm the ship's counselor.
Ahh.
I'm afraid you wouldn't find
much work here, Counselor.
I'd book my next vacation
at your hotel if you had one.
Well, in that case,
I shall have to
have them build one.
The biosphere's superstructure
will never withstand
the tectonic shocks.
The environment
would be compromised.
That's how I see it.
Your ship...
what kind of energy output
is it capable of generating?
We have a matter/anti-matter
warp reaction system--
the most powerful in Starfleet.
Normally kicks plasma up
into the terawatt range.
Why?
Well, either we're
going to have to move,
or that fragment is...
( chuckling )
We can move a small moon
or an asteroid,
but a stellar core fragment?
That's much too massive
for our tractor beam.
What's that?
A wild idea.
Purely theoretical.
A multi-phase tractor beam?
When we first spotted
the fragment approaching,
I came up with the idea,
but we can't generate the kind
of energy we would need.
You can.
LA FORGE:
We'd need Hannah on the ship.
MARTIN: No.
HANNAH: With my theories
and their equipment,
we might be able to alter
the fragment's path.
It's our only chance
to avoid evacuation.
No one had ever come here
and no one had
ever left until today.
This is a date to note
in our history books.
This is in
direct violation
of the intentions
of our founders, Aaron.
I don't think they
intended us to die, Martin.
Her absence will create
an additional imbalance.
Temporarily.
Circumstances require us
to be flexible.
We have no idea how molecular
transport will affect her DNA.
It won't affect
her DNA at all.
There's been over a century
of evidence to prove that.
You can go, Hannah.
May I return later?
I look forward to it.
Enterprise,
three to beam up.
Energize.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
Commander La Forge and Hannah
Bates have spent three days
trying to find a way to adjust
the path of the core fragment.
If they do not succeed
in the next 48 hours,
we will need to
begin evacuation.
I believe some will choose
to risk death
rather than leave, Captain.
You've spent a good deal
of time on the surface.
How do you suggest
we change their minds?
I'm not sure we can.
It would mean abandoning
their fundamental way of life.
They've managed to turn
a dubious scientific
endeavor into dogma.
You don't approve
of genetic engineering.
It was a bad idea
whose time has long passed.
They seem to have
made it succeed.
They've given away
their humanity with this
genetic manipulation.
Many of the qualities
that they breed out--
the uncertainty,
self discovery,
the unknown--
these are many of the qualities
that make life worth living.
Well, at least to me.
I wouldn't want to
live my life
knowing that my future
was written,
that my boundaries
had been already set.
Would you?
I've asked myself that question
a lot during the past few days.
I don't know.
I doubt it.
Nevertheless,
it's what they believe in,
and it won't be an easy matter
to talk them into leaving.
This leader of theirs, Conor,
he seems to be a reasonable man.
I find him very reasonable.
Open to suggestions,
thoughtful,
quite disarming.
The perfect administrator.
I'm sure.
Will he leave when he sees
there's no other choice?
I don't know.
I hope so.
You admire him.
Yes.
Then help him to see
the reality
of what may happen
to his colony.
If he makes
the right decision--
if he's as good a leader
as he's designed to be--
then perhaps the others
will follow.
If we increase the warp power
transfer by 80%...
It's just going to blow
the emitters again.
We won't be able
to reinforce the conduit
to hold that power level.
It just doesn't work.
( frustrated sighing )
I haven't had any sleep
in so long
my eyelids feel like they have
lead weights attached to them.
( sighing )
Ahh.
Geordi...
Hmm?
Were you always blind?
I'm sorry.
I probably shocked the hell out
of you, didn't I?
No.
I'll put it back on.
Don't. I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to embarrass you.
I've never been embarrassed
by this, Hannah.
Never.
I was born blind.
I've always been this way.
May I see it,
your visor?
Yeah, sure.
So...
I guess if I'd been
conceived on your world,
I wouldn't even
be here now, would I?
No.
No, I'd have been terminated
as a fertilized cell.
It was the wish of our founders
that no one have to suffer
a life with disabilities.
Who gave them
the right to decide
whether or not
I should be here?
Whether or not I might have
something to contribute?
I don't know what to say.
Here you go.
How does it work?
Well...
the visor scans
the electromagnetic spectrum
from one hertz
to 100,000 terahertz,
converts it all to
usable frequencies
and then transmits
that information directly
to my brain.
What about
the data conversion rate?
How do you avoid
a sensory overload?
A bank of preprocessors
compresses the data stream
into pulses.
You see, that way,
my visual cortex never...
Wait a minute.
Wait just a minute.
We should be able to send
a high-energy pulse
through the tractor system.
If it's short enough, it
shouldn't overload the emitters.
The technology
is right here.
If we could adapt those
pulse compression routines
and then apply them
to the warp power conduits...
We'd have to avoid
tractor force rebounding,
but that shouldn't
be hard.
Sure, with a few
modifications...
Oh, that's perfect.
What?
If the answer to all of this
is in a visor
created for a blind man
who never would have
existed in your society.
No offense intended.
( playing a Chopin prelude )
( rumbling )
Please, Matthew, continue.
( music resumes )
It's hard to believe.
So much loveliness here
just a few meters away
from such desolation.
It's hard to believe
we're about to lose it.
This may sound
incredibly simplistic,
but can't you
re-engineer
all this on
another planet?
A nursery rhyme my mother
used to read to me
has been running round and round
my mind since all this began.
A nursery rhyme?
"Humpty Dumpty
sat on a wall.
had a great fall.
BOTH:
"All the king's horses
and all the king's men
couldn't put Humpty
together again."
Why do we tell our children
such ghastly stories?
Perhaps to prepare them
for times like these.
We are every bit
as fragile as an egg,
and as impossible
to reconstruct.
We are integrated
and refined to such a degree
that any fundamental change
would lead to chaos.
I'm so sorry, Aaron.
I wish I could
do something to help.
You have helped.
You've been wonderful
these past few days.
You've been
my counselor.
No...
A counselor has to maintain
a discreet distance.
I'd rather think of us
as friends.
Friends?
That just won't do
either...
will it?
Aaron...
I must confess,
part of me knows
that if I transport
through these walls,
you'll be on
the other side.
This is wrong.
Terribly wrong.
In order to move the core
fragment to a safe trajectory,
we needed our tractor beam
to be able to handle
high-powered pulses.
And we needed a more efficient
emitter to do that.
About four times
more efficient.
But we couldn't get
anywhere near that
without overloading
the emitter arrays.
So we added a little visor
technology to the process
and were able to boost
the effective force,
and at the same time,
lower the power conduit
stress levels.
What's the increase
in efficiency?
Up to almost 300%.
That's not enough.
HANNAH: That's true.
We won't be able to move
the fragment as far as
we'd like to, but...
But...
if we also fortify
the biosphere's structural
integrity at the same time...
With some of the shield
improvements that I've
discovered here, it could work.
Of course, we'll have
to lend them some of our
engineering support crews.
Advise Mr. Conor. Number One,
brief the appropriate officers.
Prepare them for transport
as soon as Mr. Conor approves.
Yes, sir.
You're up early.
I'm still on
Enterprise time.
Aaron...
I'm going back
to the ship.
I'm not going to
see you again.
Why?
Because it's
the right thing to do.
I'm not convinced of that.
You know it as well as I do.
You're angry.
Yes, I'm angry.
I'm angry with myself
for allowing this to happen.
Deanna...
I could fall in love
with you so easily...
but we both know the end
of that story, don't we?
How would Martin feel
about introducing
half-Betazoid DNA
into the genetic balance?
If we have to evacuate,
anything's possible.
Listen to yourself.
A few days ago,
you wouldn't even talk to us.
This is my fault.
I'm so sorry.
I need you here.
This doesn't
have to happen again.
I have to go.
Good news, Aaron.
We should be able to change
the course of the core fragment,
but we'll also need
to fortify the structure.
And we're going to
need help to do it.
We'll need to bring
down engineering crews
from the Enterprise
to work with your people
for the next 48 hours.
Engineering crews?
They have to install
five new shield generators
and power supplies.
50 officers are waiting
for your approval
to transport down.
We don't have
much time, Aaron.
Is there any other choice?
None.
Enterprise, you may begin
transport when ready.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
the Enterprise has moved
to a parallel course
with the core fragment.
We must adjust its trajectory
by a minimum of 1.2 degrees
to insure
the colony's safety.
Bring us within range of
the fragment, Ensign.
Aye, sir.
You may proceed,
Mr. La Forge.
Yes, sir.
Good luck.
You, too.
Engage tractor beam.
Okay, let's give it a try.
Shutting down
non-critical systems.
Emitter circuits
170% over standard.
Increasing impulse power
to tractor emitters.
E.P.S. power levels rising.
Transferring warp power
to tractor beam generator.
Graviton generator's
operating normally.
Surge pulse
now synchronized.
Emitters radiating
at 320% over standard.
Bridge, we need more power.
Reduce life-support to minimum
requirements, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
390% over standard.
Come on, come on.
No change in
the fragment's course.
We've got to increase
the pulse frequency.
The emitter circuits
won't hold for long.
We don't need them
for long.
400% over standard.
Okay.
Now we're getting there.
Fragment's moved .4 degrees
off its previous heading... .65.
It's working.
We have lost one of
the emitter circuits, sir.
Life-support failure...
decks nine, twelve and thirteen.
Engage evacuation procedures
for those decks.
Geordi, we are going to need
power back soon.
LA FORGE: Acknowledged.
Fragments new
heading adjustment
is at 1.01 degrees.
Is it enough?
Not yet. Hold on.
We've lost the second lateral
emitter circuit.
Losing life-support systems
on decks five through nine.
Evacuation procedures
initiated.
Mr. La Forge?
LA FORGE: Hold on, Captain.
Ship-wide life-support failure
in 15 seconds, sir.
Almost there, Geordi.
Course shift is at
1.16 degrees.
Termination of all
life-support in five seconds.
1.18!
Now, Mr. La Forge.
Yes, sir. Shutting down
all tractor emissions.
Transferring power
back to life-support.
One point... two!
We've got it!
Life-support normal
on all decks.
Mr. Data?
The fragment's course
has been altered
by 1.21 degrees, sir.
Hail the colony.
Yes, Captain?
PICARD: Success, Mr. Conor.
With the upgrades
to your biosphere,
the core fragment should
no longer be a danger.
I cannot adequately express
my appreciation to your crew.
Is Hannah able to hear me?
Yes, yes.
Go ahead, Aaron.
CONOR: This is an historic
achievement, Hannah.
You've done a wonderful thing
for our people.
Thank you.
We look forward to honoring you
appropriately when you return.
Thank you again, Captain.
Conor out.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
the stellar core fragment
has passed safely
out of the Moab system.
The colony was shaken
by powerful tremblers,
but fortunately
there were no injuries
and only minor damage
was reported.
Energize.
That should do it.
All members of
the Enterprise crew
are accounted for,
Mr. Conor.
They've been invaluable,
Commander, thank you again.
If there's nothing else,
we can be on our way.
Would you tell Deanna Troi
for me that I'm sorry
I didn't get the opportunity
to say good-bye personally?
I'm sure she'll feel
the same way.
( alarm sounding )
A breach in the biosphere.
Get Hannah Bates.
Apparently the refortification
wasn't adequate.
There's definite
structural damage.
It appears that the tectonic
shifts created a breach.
Can it be repaired?
I don't know.
I'll have to run
a diagnostic in the lab.
Unless we seal it and fast,
we may have to evacuate.
How long do we have?
Uh, based on the level of
toxicity I'm reading,
it may only be
a matter of hours.
You mind if I give her
a hand, Commander?
By all means.
Isn't it amazing,
after all we went through?
Yeah.
Amazing.
It looks bad.
It's cracked
well beneath the surface.
Why are you doing this?
What do you mean?
There's no breach.
What are you talking about?
Look at it.
It's right here.
I measured the toxic leak.
You saw me.
Hannah, my visor's
positronic scan
would have detected
the leak
and its molecular
pattern enhancer
would have picked up
even the smallest crack.
The damn thing doesn't
miss much, does it?
Fine.
I'll tell them the truth.
Will that make you happy?
Why are you doing this?
I was born to be one of
the best scientific minds
of my generation.
And in the past five days,
I have encountered technology
that I had barely imagined.
And I've got to ask myself,
if we're so brilliant,
how come we didn't invent
any of these things?
Well, maybe necessity really
is the mother of invention.
You never really look
for something until you need it.
But all my needs have been
anticipated and planned for
before I was even born.
All of us in this colony have
been living in the Dark Ages.
It's like we're victims
of a 200-year-old joke.
Until you came,
all we could see was to
the wall of our biosphere.
Suddenly our eyes
have been opened
to the infinite
possibilities.
Asylum?
She wants to leave
the colony.
She may not be
the only one.
The science teams that
went down to the surface
fielded a lot of questions
from the colonists
who were more than curious about
what's outside their world.
Well, why shouldn't we
grant them asylum?
We can't do that.
We have to do that.
Do you understand what
it would do to the colony?
I understand that
these are human beings,
Counselor,
with free will.
If she wants to leave,
she has every right to.
And what happens to the colony
if she does and others join her?
The society is
genetically integrated.
Suddenly there would be
gaps, missing pieces.
It would destroy them.
There must be something
we can do to help.
We may have done too much
to help them already, Doctor.
Well, we saved them
from destruction.
PICARD:
Did we?
Counselor, I think it's time
you took me to meet Mr. Conor.
Transporter room three.
Computer, halt.
Captain, I have
to tell you something,
and it isn't easy for me
because I've used
very poor judgement.
Actually, I've acted
quite unprofessionally.
Counselor,
what is it you say?
Take a deep breath.
Conor and I have had
a relationship.
I see.
It should never have happened.
I knew there was
concern about
outside influences, and...
I should have been
more careful.
What is your status
with him now?
I did not intend
to see him again.
Would you prefer not
to return to the surface?
No, I think I should
come with you,
but I wanted you to know
before we went down.
I appreciate that.
Computer, resume.
I wanted so much
to help him...
to be there for him, but...
the more I was...
Deanna.
We all went into this
with the best of intentions.
I should have walked away
as soon as I saw
what was happening.
But you didn't...
and that's human.
We make mistakes.
Genetic manipulation or not,
nobody's perfect.
You would ignore
the welfare of the colony
for your own
selfish interests?
The welfare of this colony
would be best served
by rejoining the human race.
She has been contaminated
by the people on that ship.
Aaron.
Mr. Conor, I believe that
you and I should talk.
This is your doing.
We never should have
answered your hails.
If we'd followed
that advice, Martin,
we'd all be dead by now.
So much for the welfare
of this colony.
You are not
taking her with you.
I'm leaving, and I'll
tell you something else,
there are at least
a dozen others who are
ready to go with me.
Hannah, let's allow Aaron and
Captain Picard to discuss this.
Why don't we
go for a walk?
There's nothing else
for them to talk about.
Martin.
I think it would be
helpful if I...
I want to talk
to Captain Picard alone.
But...
Thank you, Martin.
The irony is he's the one
who saw this coming
from the moment
you arrived.
Because I didn't want
to hear him,
I chose not to listen.
You made decisions you felt
would save your colony.
No.
I wish it were that simple.
I'm afraid I can't
forgive myself so easily.
You see, Captain...
I know what Hannah Bates
is feeling.
I've been feeling it
as well.
I found your people
intriguing,
stimulating,
as she has.
I've been every bit as curious
about you as the next man,
but I am not
the next man.
I am the leader of
these people,
and every genetic fiber
in my being
demands that
I protect them.
And instead,
I have betrayed them.
I have allowed
this to happen.
We've both allowed
Then let us both find a way to
stop it from going any further.
I wish I could see a way.
Picard, I was born
to govern this colony,
not to dismantle it.
If you force them to stay,
you will be suppressing
their human rights.
If even a handful leave,
the damage to this society
will be devastating.
What about the rights of those
who would stay behind?
They are the ones will
inherit the social chaos
that will follow
for generations.
Your arrival
created this problem.
Your departure solves it.
That is simplistic.
Refuse them passage.
I cannot ignore
the requests of people--
humans--
who ask for transport
away from here.
Nor can you ignore the fact
that thousands will suffer
if you agree to take them.
And as suffering grows,
more will demand to leave.
We are witnessing
the end of this existence.
I implore you, Captain.
Do not let this happen.
You would have me
make the decision for you,
but I can't do that.
I am willing to talk
to these people with you.
And I will urge them not
to make an impulsive choice,
but if finally,
they choose to leave,
the Enterprise
will not turn them away.
Captain Picard has decided
to grant transport
to any individuals who wish
to leave Genome colony.
I am asking you to stay.
Aaron, don't you see
we can't be happy here
any longer?
We were innocent.
It will never be
that way again.
The experiences
of the past week
will become
part of our heritage.
We will adjust.
In a few generations...
We're not willing to
stay here a few generations.
All right.
Then give me six months.
Just wait six months
before you leave.
What will that accomplish?
It's true that
our presence here
has had an unintended
influence on your society,
but it's done and there is
no way to undo it.
But feelings are
running very high.
Perhaps it's not
such a bad idea
that you should take
adequate time
to weigh carefully
the consequences
of what you're
about to do.
We are prepared to
return in six months.
In other words,
we are being asked to
stay here for six months
while they pressure us
to change our minds.
In five days, you've seen only
the most superficial evidence
of what life is like
outside this biosphere.
Would you ever choose to live
aboard a ship in a bottle,
Captain?
You are in command
of a starship.
You live to explore
the unknown.
We ask for that
same privilege.
Hannah...
this is your home.
We are all, in a sense,
your family.
Don't we deserve
an opportunity
to open a dialogue on
this issue at the very least?
I am only asking
for six months.
It won't make any difference.
You'll only be putting
the people of this colony
through unnecessary
pain and anguish.
You are the ones
causing pain and anguish
in this colony-- you!
Don't you see, Aaron,
it's over?!
It's time for you to lead
our people into a new era.
You could
come with us.
When you're ready
to come home...
you will be welcome.
What will you do now?
Attempt to assess
the damage--
spend the rest of my life
on the near impossible task
of rebuilding this society
without the proper pieces.
Aaron, you acted in the best
interests of your people.
There was no way to
avoid what happened.
I replay each step
in my mind
looking for the wrong turn,
a mistake in judgement.
I can find only one.
And as hard as I try,
I cannot regret
even that one.
In fact, I'm quite certain
that given the opportunity,
I would choose to make
the same mistake again.
I can only wonder why
with all the hundreds
of genetically compatible women,
I would fall in love with you.
Don't say that.
Perhaps it's your imperfections
which make you so unique.
But I am in love with you,
Deanna Troi...
and I will always be.
( chiming )
Come.
The colonists
are all on board, sir.
How many finally?
Twenty-three.
If ever
we needed reminding
of the importance of
the Prime Directive, it is now.
The Prime Directive
doesn't apply.
They're human.
Doesn't it?
Our very presence
may have damaged,
even destroyed
their way of life.
Now, whether or not we agree
with that way of life--
whether they're human or not
is irrelevant, Number One.
We are responsible.
We had to respond
to the threat
of the core fragment,
didn't we?
Of course we did.
But in the end,
we may have proved just
as dangerous to that colony
as any core fragment
could ever have been.