Captain's Log,
Stardate 45494.2.
We're investigating
a series of subspace signals
that may indicate
intelligent life
in the Epsilon solar system.
We are within sensor range.
The characteristic response
to the Kriskov gambit
is to counter
with the El-Mitra exchange--
particularly since
I have already taken
both of your rooks.
By missing that opportunity
you have left
your king vulnerable.
We'll see.
As you wish, Counselor.
Check.
Intriguing.
You have devised a completely
unanticipated response
to a classic attack.
You will checkmate my king
in seven moves.
Data, chess isn't just a game
of ploys and gambits.
It's a game of intuition.
Hmm. You are a challenging
opponent, Counselor.
Thanks.
But don't think a compliment's
going to get you out of our bet.
You owe me one Samarian Sunset,
made in the traditional style,
as only you
can make it, Data.
I will honor our agreement.
Raise your arm to the side.
Is that it?
I'm afraid so.
What do you think?
Well, it looks
like you tucked
when you should have
flattened out.
Something like that.
Turn your head
to the left.
Ow.
Some tearing
of the ligaments--
nothing we can't take care of.
Good.
If I remember correctly
the last time
you graced my sick bay
you were diving off the cliffs
of heaven on Sumiko IV.
Holodeck program 47-C.
Same thing.
Only, that time
I flattened out
when I should have tucked.
Well, as your doctor,
I would like to recommend
the emerald wading pool
on Cirrus IV.
It's a lot safer.
Navigators on this ship
have been doing flight
handling assessments
the same way
for years, Ensign.
And I found
a better way.
Bridge.
Do you mind if we discuss
changes in procedure
before you make them?
If I had to come
to you in advance
and asked you
to do it my way...
I might have said...
No.
Yes, maybe.
The point is,
I didn't get the chance.
The point is, with all
due respect, Commander,
you are trying to
turn me into your idea
of the model officer.
The rules on this ship
do not change
just because Ro Laren
decides they do.
WORF:
We are picking up
a subspace signal, Captain.
Sensors indicate
a small spacecraft ahead.
LA FORGE:
The configuration
is unfamiliar.
Nothing in our
database comes close.
Within visual range.
On screen.
PICARD:
Analysis, Mr. Worf.
No discernible armament.
Reading one life-form
aboard.
Hail the vessel.
No response.
LA FORGE:
We're being scanned.
And it's not like any sensor
system I've ever seen.
Shall we raise shields?
No.
Let's, uh...
let's begin this with
a show of good faith.
Sir, the scans are now
matching the frequency
of our optical data network.
It could be an attempt to
access our computer system.
Scanning intensity
has increased
by 1,500%.
Shields up.
One Samarian Sunset,
made in the traditional style.
(ping)
It's beautiful.
I hope you enjoy it.
The scanning signal
has penetrated our shields.
Computers are going down.
Take evasive action.
The helm's not responding.
What happened?
What the hell...?
I don't know
who any of you are.
Nor do I.
I don't...
I don't even
remember who I am.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Looks like we're all
in the same boat.
RIKER: Make that
the same starship.
But who are we?
What are we doing here?
It looks like
I'm the pilot.
We're not going anywhere now.
The helm's dead.
But you still know
how to work it.
Yes.
This console has
tactical configuration.
Yes.
Phaser power status.
Intruder scan.
Torpedo guidance.
But they do not
appear to be operable.
PICARD: Clearly we still possess
certain skills.
It would seem we know
how to operate this ship,
but our identities
have somehow been erased or...
or suppressed.
We are on the Bridge.
There's a good chance
this is our ship.
It looks like
you're the leader.
WORF:
Perhaps we should not
jump to conclusions.
I am decorated as well.
Look, it seems to me
that determining leadership
is not crucial right now.
We... we need to find out
who we are and...
well, what we're
doing out here.
But how did this happen?
What did this to us?
Better still, who
did this to us?
I've got some intermittent
sensor readings here.
The scan keeps repeating itself
like it's stuck,
but it looks like
there's metallic debris
right in front of us.
Distance: 17 kilometers.
The remains
of another ship?
That's a good
possibility.
WORF:
Well, perhaps we were
engaged in battle.
If they stunned us with
some type of bioelectric field,
that could have
wiped out our memories.
Then we fired back,
destroyed them.
But if that presumption
is correct
then we could have
sustained other damage.
Um...
Computer, status report.
No voice interface.
No interface, period.
Hey, got something.
I've accessed
the basic system directories.
Can we get
a general status report?
Life support systems
throughout the ship
are fully operational.
Navigation, propulsion...
off-line.
What about
communications?
Completely disrupted.
That rules out
a distress signal.
If we even knew
where to send it.
Do we have an onboard
communications system?
We do now.
Well, let's use it.
This ship must have a crew.
They may still have
their memories.
We should be careful
what we say.
There could be
a boarding party
somewhere on the ship.
Bridge to
all personnel.
Select a representative
from your group
to contact the bridge
and report on your status.
WORF: Remain where you are
and stay calm.
Bridge out.
Well, that
helps a lot.
Report on our status.
I wonder if everyone
is in the same condition
as we are.
This hurts.
How's that?
Thanks.
I didn't even think.
I just picked it up
and knew how to use it.
At least I have an idea
of what I'm doing here.
But what about me?
I mean, I'm a patient
in a bathing suit.
That doesn't say much.
No, it doesn't.
Do you have any
clothes around here
I could borrow?
At least until I figure out
where the swimming pool is?
RO:
The network appears to be
inducting the power
with electromagnetic
conduits here
located along each turboshaft.
We've heard from all decks.
There are over
a thousand people on board.
Everyone's had
their memories affected
in the same way we have.
I have just
completed a survey
of our tactical systems.
We are equipped
with ten phaser banks,
250 photon torpedoes,
and a high-capacity
shield grid.
We're a battleship.
Yes, it appears so.
This turbolift system gives us
access to the rest of the ship.
That sounds like
the next logical step.
We should start with
the most crucial areas first.
Main engineering--
Deck 36.
I'm on my way.
Oh, wait a minute.
We've got to coordinate
our efforts here first.
I just need
to do something.
Look, I feel the
same way, we all do,
but if anything's
going to get done...
I know. I just...
it's really an ugly feeling.
I don't like being
so out of control.
Well, we're going to have
to depend on each other
if we're going to
get through this, okay?
Okay.
We're going
to search the ship.
Very well.
Proceed.
LA FORGE:
I'll go with you.
I want to get my hands
on the computer core--
see if we can reestablish
control from there.
I've accessed the optical data
network for the computer core.
I can monitor every system
that's routed through here.
Warp and impulse drives
are reading
within tolerance levels,
and so are the tactical arrays--
defensive and offensive.
Everything looks
functional.
Now, if we could just
access the control systems,
we could get them
up and running.
According to these
schematics,
the engineering computer core
access is down that corridor.
Weapons, propulsion,
and shields are the priorities.
We could be in danger
of another attack.
That's where I'll start.
We'll begin our crew survey
on decks five through ten.
When you get
those systems going,
try to pull up
the personnel files.
It would be nice
if we all had names.
All right?
Good luck.
Yeah. You, too.
So far, our survey teams
have found
no deaths or injuries
among the crew.
Shuttlecraft
are all operational
as are the transporters.
But no one they've
talked to knows any more
about their identities
than we do.
Engineering is working
on accessing
the control systems.
As soon as the ship
is operational
we must make it
combat-ready.
Well, I would recommend
that, before we
prepare for combat,
we try to access
the ship's logs--
find out who we are.
What our purpose
here might be.
Well, I disagree.
We must first make ourselves
ready for battle.
That is the highest priority.
LA FORGE:
Engineering to bridge.
Go ahead.
I've regained control
of navigation, propulsion,
weapons and communications.
We should be able
to tie them into the bridge
in just a few minutes.
Well done.
Now we are ready.
Question is...
for what?
The phasers
are operational.
We now have full
tactical control.
We should run
a complete diagnostic
on all command systems.
A full diagnostic
would require us
to take our
systems off-line.
We would be defenseless.
If we're going to trust
our lives to these systems,
we should be certain
that they're not going to fail.
The computer
was damaged.
Some processors
might still be down.
Proceed with the diagnostic.
What have you found, Doctor?
Not much.
The brain scans
I've run are unusual,
but there's no damage
to the hippocampus--
that suggests that we still
have our long-term memories,
but somehow they're
being blocked.
PICARD:
Is it possible to bypass
these normal pathways?
To get at these memories
some other way?
That's what I'm hoping.
What I need now is to see
some normal brain scans
for comparison.
Is there any chance I can
get the crews' medical files?
No, we are currently running
a full diagnostic.
Computer resources
are limited.
The medical records
are our next priority.
Thank you.
I guess these are my quarters,
but I don't remember anything.
If it's any
comfort, we're all
in the same situation,
so stay put for now.
We'll be back in touch.
Okay, sir. Thanks.
WOMAN: I'm really sorry.
That's all I need
for now.
Well... that's it
for the living
quarters on this deck.
What's next?
It's a large room up ahead
called "Ten-Forward."
Let's go.
So, if everything
were back to the way
it was supposed to be,
what do you think you'd
be doing right now?
I'd be having more fun
than searching
the ship, I'd imagine.
Fun?
Well, with that holodeck
we just saw,
I think I could conjure up
an interesting program or two.
Now, that's
disappointing.
Why?
You don't strike
me as a man
who needs a holodeck
to have a good time.
( concerned conversations )
Who reported to the bridge
from this group?
TROI: I did.
Have you found out anything
that might give us some insight
into what happened?
Not specifically,
but there are two things
that seem unusual.
The bartender
is an artificial life-form.
Can I get you something?
A beverage?
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
Your memories
are gone as well?
The data banks
that identify who I am
are not functioning.
You were going to mention
something else.
TROI:
I don't know if
it means anything,
but I seem to have an ability
that the others don't.
I have a very strong sense
of what other people
are feeling.
At times, it's almost...
Is something wrong?
No...
Just for a moment,
you seemed familiar.
You remember me?
Not exactly.
I mean, I don't know
who you are
but there's
something about you.
WORF:
Bridge to survey team.
Survey team here.
Go ahead.
We have accessed
the personnel files.
Report to the bridge
immediately.
We're on our way.
Computer, give me
a biographical listing
of all personnel
responsible for the primary
operation of this ship.
COMPUTER: A full biographical
listing is not available.
Is there any list
of the ship's senior officers?
The crew manifest
is available.
That's better than nothing.
Give me the crew manifest.
Commanding Officer,
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Executive Officer,
Commander Keiran MacDuff.
Second Officer,
Commander William Riker.
Operations Officer,
Lieutenant Commander Data.
Chief Medical Officer,
Dr. Beverly Crusher.
Ship's Counselor, Lieutenant
Commander Deanna Troi.
Chief Engineer, Lieutenant
Commander Geordi La Forge.
Security Chief,
Lieutenant Worf.
Helm Officer, Ensign Ro Laren.
Commander... MacDuff,
have the other officers listed
here report to the bridge.
Aye, sir.
Your next priority
will be to retrieve
any information you can
about this ship's mission.
Contact the operations
officer to assist you.
Aye, sir.
He's in Ten-Forward--
waiting tables.
Captain.
I regret my
recent behavior.
I assumed an attitude
of authority
that was... unwarranted.
Mr. Worf, we're all doing
the best we can
in a difficult situation.
Think nothing more of it.
Thank you, Captain.
We haven't finished a full
search of the computer records
but we have found out
quite a bit.
This vessel is called
the Enterprise.
We are part
of an organization
called the United
Federation of Planets.
The Federation is currently
in a state of war.
With whom?
LA FORGE:
The Lysian alliance.
They're a genocidal race
determined to destroy us.
The war has been
going on for years.
DATA:
Starfleet Command believes
the Lysians
are using a new weapon
which has shifted the balance
of power to their favor.
Over the last two months,
14 Federation vessels
have been captured,
apparently very easily,
their crews held captive
on Lysia.
What do we know
about this weapon?
DATA: Our scientists
theorize the Lysians
are using an energy wave--
either plasma-based
or a subspace
interference pattern.
The weapon severely disrupts
a starship's computer system
as well
as the mental functions
of its crew.
That's what
happened to us?
Mr. La Forge, do we
have any record
of our current mission?
Yes, sir.
We are approximately here.
We've been ordered
to cross into Lysian territory
and destroy
their central command.
This is it-- the nerve center
for the entire
Lysian military operation.
Captain, there's been
a great deal of damage
to our computer system.
Maybe we're not getting
the correct information.
What are you saying?
That we get confirmation
of this mission
from our headquarters.
If we use subspace radio,
we will be detected.
There could be
thousands of lives at stake.
Our orders
specifically require us
to maintain radio silence.
DATA:
Our mission is part
of a highly
coordinated effort
to put an end to the war.
There are other vessels
on other fronts,
all working according
to an intricate plan.
We're the linchpin
to the operation.
If we don't destroy
the central command
the entire effort will fail.
He's right, Captain.
Our choice is clear.
Commander MacDuff,
set a course
for the Lysian
central command.
These are your quarters.
Thanks for your help.
Come in for a minute?
Recognize anything?
It's like it belongs
to someone else.
Nothing feels right.
This room, this ship...
most of all,
this war we're fighting.
I don't imagine
war ever feels right.
I suppose that's true.
What is it?
That same feeling.
You seem familiar.
You're the only thing
that does.
Can you remember anything
specific about us?
I don't know.
It's... it's more like
remembering an emotion--
feelings that you're
somehow associated with.
I hope they're
good feelings.
Yes, they are.
This entire situation
is a little bit unnerving.
It's been a long day.
We've all been
through a lot.
We certainly have.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night.
( paper rustling )
Hi.
I know I didn't get
the wrong room.
I just didn't like the way
my quarters were decorated.
Besides,
I have this funny feeling
that maybe I spend
most of my off hours here.
Really?
For all we know, you
and I could be married.
For all we know,
you and I could hate each other.
Sort of exciting,
isn't it?
We just don't know.
We might regret this.
Regret what?
Aren't you being
a little presumptuous?
Like I said,
I just didn't like
the way my quarters
were decorated.
Maybe we should
switch quarters.
Maybe we should stay right
here and see what happens.
What if I snore in my sleep?
What makes you think you're
going to get any sleep?
WORF:
Captain, we have crossed
the Lysian border.
PICARD:
Take us out of warp, Ensign.
Go to three-quarters impulse.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Worf, maintain
a continuous sensor sweep.
Aye, sir.
How long till we reach
their central command?
At our current speed,
approximately 37 hours.
Captain, I am picking up
a vessel directly ahead.
Can you identify
it, Mr. Data?
The ship matches
the Starfleet description
of a Lysian destroyer,
a short-range attack vessel
with disrupter-style weapons
and a standard crew of 53.
Within visual range.
On screen.
WORF:
The destroyer is
increasing its speed.
They are moving
to intercept.
Evasive maneuver
sequence Delta.
RO:
Yes, sir.
They are matching
our maneuvers.
Activating
phaser arrays.
Ready to fire, sir.
Stand by.
Captain, our orders
were to destroy
all Lysian warships.
I'm aware of that, Commander.
Tactical analysis, Mr. Data.
The destroyer
has minimal shields.
Their disrupter capacity
appears to be
only 2.1 megajoules.
They're no match
for the Enterprise.
Captain, the destroyer
is hailing us.
Open a channel.
No! Their new weapon--
whatever it is that erased
our computers and our memories--
maybe this is how they do it--
over communication channels.
It is conceivable, sir.
It's also possible
they just want to talk to us.
I think we should respond.
Captain, the ship
is hailing us again.
If you're wrong,
it could mean our destruction.
We can't take the risk, Captain.
DATA:
The Lysians have stopped
transmitting, Captain.
They are powering up
their disrupters.
They have locked onto us, sir.
Full shields.
WORF:
Shields up.
( laser blast )
Captain?
Return fire.
WORF: The ship
has been destroyed.
Maintain this
course, Ensign.
Three-quarters impulse.
RO: Yes, sir.
Well done, Captain.
The Lysian central command
would have received
any transmission from
the destroyer by now.
They're going to be
on alert.
RO: I recommend
a randomly vectored approach
to our target.
It would be our best chance
of avoiding any sort of pursuit.
Agreed.
Doctor, the success
of this mission
would be much more likely if
we could get our memories back.
Is there anything
you can do?
I found several cases
resembling our condition
in the medical index.
The causes are different
but the cure is similar
in each case.
Could the same
treatment work for us?
That's what I'm hoping.
It involves
increasing the activity
of the medial temporal region
of the brain.
Using short-term
memory synapses
to retrieve
long-term memory.
When can you start?
As soon as our medical files
become available.
It would be dangerous to attempt
treatment without them.
Mr. La Forge?
Data and I ran
into a little trouble
accessing the medical file areas
of the computer,
but, with a little time,
I'm pretty sure
we'll be able to get there.
Three hours, maximum.
Proceed.
I don't get it.
I'm still hitting
a file wall.
There appears to be
a command path discontinuity.
I shall attempt to rewrite
the locator subroutine.
You must have been
one hell of a bartender.
You know, it's too bad there
aren't more of you around.
We could certainly
use the help.
Yes.
I wonder why you're
the only one on board.
I have expended
considerable thought
with respect to my apparent
uniqueness among the crew.
Any conclusions?
Several possibilities
suggest themselves.
I may represent an entire race
of artificial life-forms.
If so, there may be
a home planet
for others of my kind--
a shared history
and a culture
of which I am not
presently aware.
Then again, you could
have been built just
for this ship.
I have considered
that possibility as well.
It may also be the case
that every starship
in the Federation
is equipped with an artificial
life-form such as myself.
Hmm.
If that's true,
maybe you all look alike--
a standard-issue android.
Hard to construct, so only
one allowed per vessel.
There is another possibility.
Perhaps my origin is unique.
In that case, I am alone.
( console beeping )
We have accessed
the information storage area.
Considerable damage has been
done to the files themselves.
The mission
reports are gone.
DATA:
As well as the crew records
and the personal logs.
So are
the medical records.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'm restless.
Mind if I visit
for a while?
Please.
What's wrong?
Everything.
Every time I think about
this war, our mission,
I feel a sense of panic,
like a hand's closing
around my throat.
You're never going to feel
good about this war--
none of us will-- but we've
got to complete our mission.
I've been doing
a little research--
trying to find out more
about William T. Riker.
What have
you discovered?
He's a musician,
for one thing.
( plays jaunty melody )
Very impressive.
No one was more
surprised than I.
So, what else has your
research uncovered
about William Riker?
He's athletically inclined.
Loves to climb mountains.
He's from somewhere
called Alaska.
Enjoys exotic food...
and takes his vacations
on a planet called Risa.
( sighs )
Ode to Psyche,
by John Keats.
Open it.
"To Will.
All my love,
Deanna."
That may explain
some of the familiar
feelings we have.
I don't know
what to think.
( door chime )
Come in.
Counselor.
Ensign.
Am I interrupting
anything?
BOTH: No.
I was just visiting.
Um...
We'll talk again
soon, Commander.
Of course.
Thank you, Counselor.
Bye.
And what was
all of that about?
Oh... we were just discussing
the situation we're all in.
Mm-hmm. Good...
because I have a feeling
that I used to be
the jealous type.
What bothers me, Captain,
is how specific this damage is.
Any records
of a personal nature,
any files that could
tell us about who we are--
those are the ones
that are gone.
That's a little too selective
to be coincidence.
As selective as what was
done to our own memories.
Skills are still in place,
but personal knowledge
is unavailable.
It is consistent
with what we know
about the new
Lysian weapon.
Doctor, is it
absolutely necessary
to see the medical files
to attempt treatment?
It would be dangerous
to do without them.
It's a risk I think
we have to take.
He's right, Captain.
I volunteer for
the procedure.
CRUSHER:
That's strange.
The diencephalic activity
is exactly the same.
There should be some increase.
Let's try broadening
the bandwidth.
Go to 30.1.
Raise the frequency as well.
Increase it by 33%.
Something's wrong
with the sequencing program.
Keiran? Keiran?
I'm all right.
What happened?
I don't know.
Something went wrong
with the sequence initiator.
We're lucky
we didn't lose you.
Did any of this work?
Do you remember anything
more about yourself?
No.
I'm sorry, doctor.
Back to square one.
( door chimes )
Come.
You wanted to
see me, Captain?
Yes, Commander.
Please come in.
Sit down.
I find myself having...
grave concerns
about our mission.
Concerns as-as
to its success?
No, no, no.
More fundamental doubts.
Whether or not it
can be justified.
I've been asking myself
the same thing.
I'm sure our superiors feel
their orders are justified.
Orders we can't
even verify.
Orders we can't ignore.
But I also can't ignore
that we have
greatly outclassed
the one enemy vessel
we've encountered
and that every single,
possible shred of information
which might shed some light
on this situation
has been conveniently
eliminated.
I feel as though
I've been handed a weapon
sent into a room,
and told to shoot a stranger.
Well, I need
some moral context
to justify that action.
And I don't have it.
I'm not content
simply to obey orders.
I need to know that
what I'm doing is right.
So do I.
I'd feel a lot better
if all the questions
were answered
and if you want
to abandon our mission
until our memories return,
that's your choice
but...
I must ask you...
is it right to risk
prolonging this war--
to allow the needless deaths
of thousands on both sides--
solely on the basis
of our moral discomfort?
( door chimes )
Come.
Lieutenant.
You wished
to see me, sir?
I did.
Please.
Memory or no, it seems clear
that both you and I
were born for battle,
more so than the others.
I thought this as well.
It's conceivable
that that is the very reason
that we have been assigned
to this vessel.
The Enterprise
has science officers,
medical specialists, engineers.
Our captain is undoubtedly
an accomplished diplomat.
But we...
we are the warriors.
There are times
for diplomacy.
This is not
one of them.
You are concerned
about the captain.
I am concerned about
completing our mission
and ending this war...
in victory.
We may soon face
a critical moment.
The success
of our mission
may hang on
a split-second decision.
A hesitation
would kill us all
and those
that are counting on us
would surely die as well.
We cannot let this happen.
That'll be all.
We are entering
the Lysian system, sir.
Slow to one-quarter
impulse.
Yes, sir.
The central command
is directly ahead--
still beyond weapon range.
Red alert.
Battle stations.
Bring us to an attack posture,
Mr. Worf.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Sensors show several
objects in our path, sir.
They are 29 meters in
length and are unmanned.
According to Starfleet records,
they're sentry pods
programmed to defend
their central command.
I read 47 of them
around the perimeter.
Tactical analysis, Mr. Data.
The pods are equipped
with fusion-generated
pulse lasers
and minimal shielding.
Not much power there.
Forward shields to maximum.
Lock phasers
on the sentry pods.
PICARD: Prepare
to return fire.
Shields up.
Phasers locked on targets.
Full impulse.
Take us straight through.
We are through
the perimeter, sir.
That was too easy.
WORF:
We have yet
to encounter
any battleships.
They may lie ahead.
Load all torpedo bays.
Ready phasers.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
Approaching central command.
Mr. Data,
scan for defenses.
I am picking up
no vessels,
no additional
sentry pods.
RIKER:
Optimal firing range
in 55 seconds.
Phaser banks ready.
Loading torpedoes.
What are
the defensive capabilities
of the central command?
Armaments consist
of four laser cannons
and 39 cobalt
fusion warheads
with magnetic propulsion.
Defensive shield output
is 4.3 kilojoules.
One photon torpedo
ought to do it.
Data, how many people
on that station?
15,311.
We're within range,
Captain.
Stand by.
Waiting on
your orders, sir.
Captain, this isn't right.
The rest of our forces
are depending on us.
How could our mortal enemy
be over 100 years behind us
in weapons technology?
Their battleships may be
on their way right now.
We must attack!
I do not fire on
defenseless people.
Mr. Worf, open a channel
to the Lysians.
Belay that order!
There's something wrong
with the captain.
I'm taking command
of this vessel.
Fire all weapons!
Mr. Worf.
( grunts )
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We are on a course
to Starbase 301.
Dr. Crusher
has been working steadily
and has restored the memories
of most of the crew.
The Lysians have identified
"Commander MacDuff"
as a Satarran--
an alien race
that's been at war
with the Lysians for decades.
I have...
I've conveyed our deepest
regrets to the Lysians
over the tragedy
of their lost ship and crew.
With all the power
that MacDuff had
to alter our brain chemistry
and manipulate the computers,
it's hard to believe
he needed the Enterprise.
The Satarran weapons technology
was no more advanced
than the Lysian.
One photon torpedo
would have ended their war.
It almost did.
( conversation and laughter )
( sighs )
I hope
I'm not interrupting.
BOTH:
No.
I was hoping
to run into you.
Please, sit down.
( groans )
Well, I'm glad I ran into the...
the two of you.
When you have no memory
of who you are
or who anybody else is,
you find yourself...
The counselor tells me
that at times like that
we might do the things that
we've always wanted to do.
She said that?
It's psychologically
valid.
RO:
Commander, don't
worry about it.
As far as I'm concerned,
you and I have shared something
that we will treasure forever.
Well, I'm a little confused.
Well, if you're
still confused tomorrow,
you know where my office is.