PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45571.2.
We are going into orbit around
an unexplored M-Class moon
of Mab-Bu VI.
Though the moon was reported
to be uninhabited
we have picked up
a weak distress call.
( staticky distress call
playing )
DATA:
The electromagnetic whirlwinds
on the moon's surface
make it virtually
impossible to locate the source
of the signal, Captain.
Any indications
of life, Mr. Worf?
Scanners read
negative, sir
but they may be affected
by the interference.
Have you ever
heard anything
like this, Data?
I believe so, Commander.
At Starfleet Academy.
The Academy?
I will verify it.
Just as I thought.
It is a Starfleet
subspace distress signal.
Standard to Daedalus-class
starships.
There hasn't been
a Daedalus-class
in service
for... what?
172 years, sir.
Are there any records
of missing ships
in this vicinity?
The USS Essex, under the command
of Captain Bryce Shumar
disappeared in this sector
over two centuries ago.
Daedalus-class.
I have accessed the subspace
transponder signature
of the Essex.
It is identical to the signal
coming from the moon's surface.
We arrived a
little late.
Mute it, Mr. Data.
With all that storm activity
down there
it isn't worth
the risk to check
on a ghost ship.
Advise Starfleet
that we have solved
the mystery of
Captain Shumar
and the Essex.
I'm not sure we have.
Someone's
down there.
Alive.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
The electromagnetic
interference on the surface
has been judged too dangerous
for anyone to transport down
so we have taken a shuttle
to investigate.
Shields are holding, sir.
Wind shear is
incredible.
Data, keep an eye
on the stabilizers.
If it's anything like
this on the ground
I don't see how
people could survive
on this moon
for very long.
Maybe they've been
living underground.
Question is, where?
I still can't locate
the source
of the damn signal.
It's bouncing around
more than we are.
Forward thrusters
have failed, sir.
We are losing power.
Enterprise!
Go ahead.
RIKER ( distorted ):
We've lost our thrusters.
Attempting to compensate
with secondary boosters.
Sir, the shuttlecraft's impulse
generators have shut down.
Commander, can
you hear me?
Enterprise to shuttle.
Please respond.
Hold on.
We're going down.
Initiating emergency
landing procedures.
Maintain the approach
attitude, Data.
I'm taking her in.
Brace for impact.
( thunder rumbling )
The shuttle has crashed
on the surface.
Do you have their position?
I am picking up
the shuttle's trace signature
but the surface interference
is distorting its position.
Can you locate them?
I think I can.
I followed their entry
almost all the way in.
We can calculate
the coordinates
from their angle
of descent.
Ow!
Your arm.
Yeah. I'm pretty sure
that's broken.
Enterprise?
It is unlikely
we will be able
to establish
communication
with the ship
given the electromagnetic
interference.
Then we'll stay in the area
until the Enterprise finds us.
Take an inventory
of the shuttle.
See if there's anything left
in there that's usable.
The ground cover
is all nonporous rock
which makes me believe
it's even less likely
there's anyone living here.
There are no instruments left
of practical value
that have not been damaged
by our landing, sir.
What is that?
That doesn't look like any
storm front I've ever seen.
The tricorder is picking up
high levels
of EM bursts
across the spectrum.
No life sign readings
other than our own.
There is someone
alive here.
I'm more certain
of it now than ever.
Well, I hope
they can find us
because there's no way
we'll find them.
They're coming.
They're coming
with the storm.
( thunder rumbling )
We can't get a pattern lock
on their communicators
because of
the EM bursts, Captain.
There's no way we can
beam them out of there.
Not under these
conditions.
The same conditions won't permit
a shuttle to land safely,
Mr. La Forge.
Any suggestions?
O'BRIEN:
Give us a minute, Captain.
Sir, let me beam down
with a pattern enhancer.
Chief, there's
no guarantee
you won't rematerialize
in a million pieces
if your signal gets caught up in
that electromagnetic whirlwind.
I can boost
the confinement beam.
One person might be
able to make it.
Captain, Chief O'Brien
wants to beam down
to the surface
with a pattern enhancer.
His chances
of making it down there safely
are no better than 50-50,
in my opinion.
Captain, a major storm
front is moving in
on the away team's
coordinates.
You're aware
of the risks, Mr. O'Brien?
Yes, sir.
I think I can make it.
All right, then.
Good luck.
Aye, sir.
( thunder rumbling )
RIKER:
Mr. O'Brien!
Nice of you
to join us.
Nice spot
for a picnic, sir.
We need to distribute
these enhancer rods
at seven-meter lengths.
That should do it.
Is this storm front
going to interfere
with the transport, Chief?
I'd really like
to get us out of here
before it hits,
Commander.
I'm supposed to be feeding
the baby lunch.
Molly gets
in a terribly foul mood
if I'm late.
I'm with you.
Lunch time, Miles!
Let's do it!
( yells )
( groans )
( screams )
Easy, Deanna.
Where...?
You're back
on the Enterprise now.
You're going to be okay.
My skin--
it's tingling.
You're experiencing
the after-images
of the electromagnetic
discharge.
The sensation
will pass.
They're all
fine, too.
Now, I want you
to take your time, Counselor.
Doctor's orders.
( door opens )
Injury report, Doctor.
Mostly minor abrasions.
Commander Riker
took the worst of it
with a broken arm.
Mr. Data.
Good work, Chief.
Thank you, sir.
Ready for duty, sir.
You're sure, Number One?
It's not the first broken bone
I've ever had.
And how are you, Counselor?
Very glad to be here.
Good. Let's go.
So, what happened down there?
It was just one
hell of a storm.
It moved in on our position
faster than anything
I've ever seen.
Was there any
evidence of life?
No, but if Troi was right
we were pretty close
to it.
Bridge. So, how do you
suggest we proceed?
We need to adjust
the scanners
so that they can penetrate
those storms.
Do you have
any ideas, Data?
We might be able
to employ virtual imaging
in order to interpolate...
( creaking ):
missing data.
Is something wrong,
Commander?
My apologies, sir.
It seems
my primary speech processors
are experiencing
a minor fluctuation.
I will have it corrected
in a moment.
Captain, may I
speak with you
for a moment--
in private?
Of course. You'll have
the Bridge, Number One.
Mr. Data, deploy sensor scans
when you're ready.
Ensign, take us
to a synchronous orbit
aligned around
our crash site.
RO:
Aye, sir.
Sir, given the EM field
properties of this moon
I recommend a search pattern
beginning in the southern
polar region.
The polar region?
That would be starting
from scratch, Mr. Data.
Our latest readings
would suggest
that we begin our scan
around our crash site.
The Essex signal
was never clearly located, sir.
A systematic survey
of the moon
from a polar orbit
might be more practical.
Well, you may be right,
but I'd like to give
the crash site
a once-over first.
Maintain our current orbit.
Understood, sir.
I've never felt
anything like it.
It was as though
they were calling to me.
Are you saying someone was
communicating telepathically?
Perhaps...
for an instant.
It was like their voices
were being carried on the wind.
What were they trying
to communicate?
I'm not sure.
But they were calling me
to the southern polar region.
I believe that's where we
should look for the Essex.
Commander,
did you override
my orbital heading?
Override them?
We've moved
into a polar orbit
and I'm locked out.
The helm isn't
responding.
Do you know anything
about this, Mr. Data?
Data?
( groans )
Security to the Bridge!
RIKER:
Computer, transfer command
to Engineering.
Full security alert.
( groans )
This way.
What happened?
He would not move
to a polar orbit.
You couldn't wait?
The Captain would
have done it for me.
Deck 36. Engineering.
Computer,
re-enable Bridge control.
Security protocol.
Authorization:
Riker Omega Three.
Report.
Data, O'Brien and Troi
tried to commandeer the ship.
They're in
Turbolift Four.
Engaging override
controls now.
They have trapped us.
What deck is this?
We are on deck ten.
Can you move us again?
I know how to override
the Bridge command.
Activate security fields,
decks eight through 15.
( console beeping )
Sir, the turbolift is
moving again.
They're still inside.
Initiate emergency bulkheads
in Turboshaft Four.
Aye, sir.
They have been stopped
at deck 13.
Mr. Worf.
Do you know
how to deactivate this?
The computer won't allow us
to override
an emergency
force field command.
My entity's artificial
substructure may be useful.
They've broken through
a security field.
Deck ten, section two.
Security to Ten-Forward!
( crying loudly )
( murmuring )
Shh.
Mama's here.
Everyone, get down
on the floor.
Miles...?
Shh...
On the floor!
Everyone down!
Now!
Miles!
( grunting )
( Molly crying )
Multiple phaser shots,
Ten-Forward.
Picard to Worf. Report.
Mr. Worf, acknowledge.
Can you hear me, Mr. Worf?
Yes, Bridge.
He can hear you.
PICARD:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Following an aborted attempt
to take control of the Bridge
Counselor Troi, Mr. Data
and Chief O'Brien
have seized Ten-Forward.
Position security teams
at both entrances.
Yes, sir.
Mr. La Forge, shut
down all computer
access to Ten-Forward.
I can't, Captain.
They've already set up
a remote security lockout.
We'd have to shut down
all computer function
in the saucer section.
Transporter Room Three,
can you get a pattern lock
on Commander Data,
Counselor Troi
and Chief O'Brien
in Ten-Forward?
Attempting to lock on, sir.
O'BRIEN:
You are correct.
They're attempting to
engage their transporters
but I know how
to shut them down.
Do it.
Bridge, the entire transporter
array has been taken off-line
and placed into diagnostic mode.
I can't override.
It'll take a couple of hours
to complete the cycle.
How many people
are down there?
Seventeen.
They just shut down the
internal scanners, too, Captain.
Dr. Crusher
to the Bridge.
On my way.
What are you doing now?
I can reverse the polarity
of their force fields
to isolate this room.
Good.
Their communicators.
Now they'll learn nothing,
except what we tell them.
They've done something
to the force fields
on deck ten, section one.
Geordi?
I don't recognize
the configurations
but they've completely
isolated Ten-Forward.
What about flooding
their air vents
with anesthezine gas?
That won't affect Data.
No rescue plan will work
unless we can knock out
all three of them.
A concussive charge would
blow out the security field
so we can go in
with our phasers on a wide beam.
Stun everybody.
Sort it out later.
Doctor, go back to
the biofilter readouts taken
of the away team's transport
from the moon's surface.
See if you can come up
with any clue
that might explain this.
Ten-Forward,
this is Captain Picard.
I am prepared to
discuss this situation.
There is no need
for further violence.
Please identify yourself.
They will now attempt
to negotiate
for the safety and
release of their people.
Interesting.
Under normal circumstances
I would be counseling
the Captain
at a time like this.
What would you tell him
to do?
I would help him find a way
to secure our trust.
What are
you looking at?
( Molly crying )
You, Klingon.
Attack me.
( beeping )
Are you afraid?
I have no fear of death.
And I have no fear
of killing you.
TROI:
Stop it!
PICARD:
Please respond, Ten-Forward.
Are there any members of my crew
who require medical assistance?
We can discuss
your wounded.
But first,
you will move the ship.
Move it where?
You will change orbit to an
inclination of 80 degrees south.
That's the southern
polar region.
That's where Data tried
to move the ship.
And that's what Troi
asked me to do, but why?
Ten-Forward,
if you could be
more specific about
our intended destination
then perhaps we could...
You have 30 seconds
to change your heading
or additional members
of your crew
will require medical attention.
We need to stabilize
this situation.
Play for time.
I suggest that we move
the ship as they've asked.
Agreed?
Set a new heading.
But take us there
as slowly as you can.
Ten-Forward, we are moving
the ship as you requested.
He's telling the truth.
Their heading has changed.
Captain, I've compared
the away team's
last transporter trace patterns
to their earlier records.
They're exactly the same
except in Data, Troi and O'Brien
there's an unusual
synaptic activity--
some kind of anionic energy.
It might be
another life-form
superimposing its neural
patterns on our people.
Why wasn't I affected?
I don't know.
The only difference
between you and the others
is that you were injured.
My broken arm.
CRUSHER:
The fracture caused
pain receptors to fire
which may have made you
immune to this energy.
If your theory is
accurate, Doctor
what would happen if we were
to inflict pain on the others?
It might force whatever it is
out of our people.
A plasma shock--
it would be painful
but it wouldn't cause
any physical harm.
I could hook up
a modified laser scanner
to a plasma inverter.
What about Data?
Well, a plasma shock
will definitely overload
his neural net.
It'll work on him, too.
We have to find a
way to penetrate
the force field
around Ten-Forward.
I might be able to interrupt
the force field
for a few seconds
but I'll be fighting
the computer for control.
Timing will be critical.
RO:
We'd have to hit
all three with a
single discharge.
If they're standing
together
it shouldn't
be a problem.
How will you gain access?
Microoptic drill
through the ceiling
and they'll
never detect it.
If this is going to work,
we have to have some way
to contain or neutralize
this anionic energy
once it's out
of our people.
Yes, Doctor.
That will be
your top priority.
Very well.
Proceed.
Bridge to Ten-Forward.
Now that we are moving
the ship as you requested
I would like to know the
nature of the injuries
to the members
of my crew.
Five of your people
have been injured.
How serious is their condition?
You, Klingon, tell him.
Captain, one person has
what looks like
a level-five phaser hit.
And four others
have secondary burns.
They require medical attention.
And our captors are not affected
by a phaser stun...
Silence, Klingon.
Ten-Forward, you must
release these people
so that they can receive
proper medical attention.
I will release no one.
If you will release them,
I will take their place.
I don't trust him.
It may be a deception.
The crew values Picard's
life above all others.
Captain Picard, we
agree to your proposal.
Expect a medical team
to accompany me.
TROI:
Acknowledged.
Sick Bay, this is Picard.
Have an emergency
medical team
meet me outside
Ten-Forward.
Sir, putting you down there
only strengthens
their position.
Number One, so long as
they're on board this ship
I'm a hostage, no matter
where I am-- we all are.
I must find out who
we're dealing with.
If La Forge and Ro
can attempt a rescue
in short order,
then let them proceed.
If they can't,
I will provide you
with another
opportunity.
Watch for it.
Yes, sir.
( Molly crying )
Shh.
Shh!
Silence that child!
( crying continues )
Shh!
I know you.
I know who you are.
And I know what this is.
She's frightened.
Why don't you just
let us go?
Shh!
No.
Make it stop!
Shh!
PICARD:
Ten-Forward
we're outside the door.
Lower the force field.
Welcome, Captain.
Allow me to
introduce myself.
I am Captain Bryce Shumar
of the Federation
Starship Essex.
The Starship Essex vanished
over 200 years ago.
Indeed. I know.
I was there.
This is my First Officer,
Commander Steven Mullen
and my Security Chief,
Lieutenant Morgan Kelly.
And you have survived
all this time as...
Spirits? Ghosts?
But you're a man who would never
believe in ghosts, Picard.
Isn't that true?
You see,
Troi knows you
and so I do, as well.
Then Counselor Troi
is still alive?
Yes, of course, she is.
I have no wish to harm her
or to harm anyone else.
I'm very pleased
to hear that.
We have been forced
to take this action, Captain
because we need your help.
My help?
Our consciousness
has been trapped on this moon
for two centuries.
We must escape this torture.
How did this happen to you?
I can't explain
how it happened.
I only know that it did.
The Essex was caught
in an electromagnetic storm
just as your shuttle was.
Moments before we crashed
the Bridge was struck
by lightning.
The ship was ripped apart.
Somehow, in that instant,
our consciousness was absorbed
into the magnetic currents
on the surface.
Why didn't you tell us this?
Why the deception?
The violence?
Because, as I said
I knew
you would not believe us.
Even now, I know you don't.
What was your
vessel's designation
and its complement?
NCC-173.
Daedalus-class starship.
Crew-- 229.
Under whose command
in this sector?
Admiral Uttan Narsu,
Starbase 12.
You will find all this
in Starfleet records.
I don't need to
see the records.
Then you know I am correct.
End this, and I will give
you whatever help you need.
No.
You don't trust us
and I can't risk trusting you.
It is taking too long.
We should have been there
by now.
He is manipulating you.
Captain Picard has every right
to be curious.
He will delay until
a rescue attempt is possible.
I know that.
I also know
that he will make every effort
to protect the lives
of his people.
Since our demands are
not excessive, Captain
I hope you will see that
it will be simpler to accede
than to risk further injuries.
What do you want?
All you need to know for now
is that we want to rest.
Simply, finally, to rest.
Section two...
"B."
"A."
Section one.
Finally.
I never want to see this part
of the Enterprise again.
I hear you-- this is
what starship designers
call "easy access."
Yeah. Yeah, this is it.
I thought we might
have a problem
with conduit number 227
but it looks like
we're going to be able
to get by it.
( groans )
Thanks.
We're through.
Good.
Let's hook up the scanner
and see what we've got.
Got it.
All three have got to be
in the circle
if this is going to work.
We're halfway home.
( quietly ):
La Forge to Crusher.
How are you doing?
I think I've come up with
an idea for a containment field.
This anionic energy seems
to be vulnerable
to the same magnetic
flux density
we monitored in the storms.
If we can duplicate it,
we can trap it
once it's out of our people.
Well, you should
be able to do that
by flooding Ten-Forward
with ionogenic particles.
Exactly what I was thinking.
RIKER:
Geordi, how long will it take
to get it all ready?
Uh, we still have to calibrate
the plasma inverter, Commander.
My guess is 45 minutes
to an hour.
I can have the containment field
ready by then.
Keep me advised.
Watch the Klingon.
I will.
Leave us.
He's confused.
Impressions,
Mr. Worf.
Spiritual possessions
of this sort have been reported
throughout Klingon history.
It is called Jat'yIn--
the taking of the living
by the dead.
Human history is full
of many similar legends.
Then you believe
they may be telling the truth?
We need
to maintain control...
Not for one moment.
Sir, they know much
about the Essex.
If it is the spirit
of Captain Shumar...
Then he should
be behaving
very much better,
don't you think?
A Starfleet Captain?
O'BRIEN:
You two, sit down.
Hey, right!
Living disembodied
for two centuries--
perhaps they've gone mad.
I assure you,
Mr. Worf
these are
not Jat'yIn.
Our job is to find out
exactly what they are
and then to determine
how to deal with...
All right, that's enough.
Stop, both of you.
You over there, you there.
Down!
O'BRIEN:
I gave you that.
( Molly cries )
In a place called
McKinley Park.
Green grass...
tall trees.
Please don't.
I hid the bracelet
in your pocket.
You were... surprised.
Don't.
( crying continues )
You said, "Miles,
you make me feel so happy."
No! Get away!
Get away from me!
TROI:
Leave her alone.
( crying continues )
PICARD:
Captain Shumar?
We'll be approaching
the southern polar region
that you've requested
in a few minutes.
I need to give
additional instructions.
Very well.
We're taking you
to our crash site.
At the southern pole.
That is correct.
Nothing our sensors
were able to detect
indicated that the Essex
went down in that region.
As I told you, Captain
the ship broke up
in the atmosphere
and the Bridge went down here.
When we reach it
you will beam what's left
of our skeletal remains
on board this ship,
and then take them
back to Earth,
for a proper burial.
You see how simple a request
this is?
Captain...
If you will let
these people go
I'll order the Bridge to
follow your instructions.
I will release no one.
If you are who you say you are,
there's no need for any of this.
We'll gladly take you home.
I wish you were truly as
open-minded as you say, Picard.
If you don't release
the hostages
I won't cooperate.
Oh, you will cooperate,
Captain.
You will cooperate,
or someone will die.
Who shall
it be, huh?
How about the Klingon?
Get another one.
You.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Pick one to die, Captain...
or I kill them both.
( crying continues )
RO:
They're all in range.
I have to do it now.
I'm only going to be able
to shut down the force field
for about seven seconds
before the computer compensates.
Well, if they're the
right seven seconds,
it'll be enough.
LA FORGE:
Bridge, prepare to release the
ionogenic field on my signal.
Standing by.
Ready?
Kill the force field.
Force field down.
RO:
Firing plasma charge.
( screaming )
Damn!
Tell them to stop,
or I kill everyone
in this room,
starting with you.
Picard to Bridge!
Abort immediately!
As you say, Captain.
Riker to La Forge.
Return to the Bridge.
( sighing )
Are you ready to cooperate?
Yes.
( panting )
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
The Enterprise has moved
into a synchronous orbit
near the southern polar region.
We await further instructions
from Ten-Forward.
Any sign of the Essex?
Negative, Commander.
Electromagnetic
disturbances are
even worse here.
Scanners can't
read a thing.
Bridge to Ten-Forward.
Intense storm activity
over the southern pole
is making it
virtually impossible
for us to pick up
any trace of the Essex.
We are giving you
the exact coordinates
of our remains on board
the wreck of the Essex.
Receiving those
coordinates now.
Can you tell what's there?
Just your basic
ionic cyclone.
I can't read a thing.
Well, I'm sure as hell
not going to beam up
whatever might be
down there.
I've got a good
excuse for you.
The transporters
aren't going to work
any better than
the scanners.
Bridge to Ten-Forward.
Whatever's blocking
our scanners
will prevent
the use of the transporters.
They're lying!
On the contrary.
We've had a difficult time
with the transporters
since we arrived here.
That's why we had to send down
the shuttle.
You should all have been
aware of that fact.
We must be able
to use the transporters.
Mr. O'Brien was the one
who safely executed
the return of
the away team.
He's the most qualified person
on board to operate
the transporters
under these circumstances.
Can you do it
from here?
No. We'll have to use
the transporter pad.
I could...
I could give you
safe passage
to a transporter pad
in one of the cargo bays.
It is a trick.
He is trying to divide us.
We must not
be separated.
I could give you all
safe passage.
Why are you suddenly
being so helpful?
Because I assume
that if you choose
to go to the cargo bay
then you won't take
all of the hostages.
Their safety is
my chief priority.
What are the risks
when we leave this room?
Without the protection
of the force fields
we are completely vulnerable.
They could use the transporter
against us.
Once the force field is down
they could beam us
back to the surface.
But there is a way
to neutralize that threat.
Bridge...
transfer all transporter
functions to Ten-Forward.
RIKER:
In order to do that
you will have to release
your computer control lockouts.
That's not true.
Let me talk to him.
Number One, I think
we have an opportunity
to end this siege.
It will require the cooperation
of all concerned.
Our... guests will
be moving shortly
to Cargo Bay Four
where the transport
will occur.
I want you to ensure
them of safe passage
between Ten-Forward
and the Cargo Bay.
Understood, Captain.
Doctor...
Mr. La Forge...
Yes, sir.
Transporter controls
are being transferred.
Ten-Forward to Bridge.
I said
all transporter controls!
Including all those
aboard your shuttlecraft.
Almost had them, Ensign.
( sighs )
Nice try.
Riker to Ten-Forward.
Remaining transporter
functions are being
transferred to you.
Once we create
our own access code
we can prevent anybody using
the transporter against us
as we go to the cargo bay.
What about the weapons?
We will each
take a hostage...
for protection.
Klingon.
Picard, you are mine.
( Molly crying )
Please, let her stay.
Lower the force field.
Security teams, stand by.
They're heading
through section five.
Mr. La Forge,
Doctor, they'll be
at their destination
in less than a minute.
They've stopped
at deck 18, sir.
Security, allow them
access into Cargo Bay Four.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
I will require
assistance.
Captain Shumar...
how do you intend to achieve
this "rest" that you so desire?
What do you mean?
Well, how do
you intend
to free yourselves
of this existence
that has so trapped
your consciousness?
It will fade as we move
further from this planet.
Really? And what is
your scientific basis for that?
I don't need a scientific basis.
Just be quiet.
Captain Shumar,
when are you going
to tell me who you really are?
I've initialized the
transporter signal.
Proceed.
They're firing up
the transporter,
Commander.
Mr. La Forge?
I've isolated
Cargo Bay Four
with a neutrino
field, sir
but it will
only take Data
and O'Brien a
couple of minutes
to override it once they
discover that it's there.
I hope that'll give
the Captain
enough time
to play his hand.
Do you know what
he's going to do?
There's only
one reason
he chose
Cargo Bay Four.
If it becomes
necessary, Ensign
you'll blow
the cargo bay hatch
on my orders.
Yes, sir.
TROI:
You're right, Picard.
It's not rest we seek,
only escape.
Escape?
We were brought
to this moon
over five centuries ago
from a star system
called Ux-Mal.
We were separated
from our bodies
and left to drift
in the storms.
Once, we almost escaped--
on board the Essex.
But that ship
was incapable
of eluding
this moon's
electromagnetic storms.
You really think
that using
their identities
would gain our sympathy?
It was a better approach
than asking you
to allow hundreds
of condemned prisoners on board.
Then this moon
is a penal colony.
That's correct.
But now, we have your ship
and your bodies
to carry us home.
I'm reading dozens
of them-- hundreds.
They have the same
anionic signature
we saw on the biofilter scans.
I think we can give
the Captain
a new bargaining chip.
Dr. Crusher,
flood the cargo bay
with your
containment field.
No!
Let them go,
or you will all die!
Your threats are
meaningless now.
We are still in
control of these
three bodies.
We will not
let them go.
Are you prepared to
sacrifice the lives
of these others?
They'll all die
when the cargo
bay hatch is blown.
You will die,
too, Picard.
I would die to save
the life of my child.
To die
defending one's ship
is the hope
of every Klingon.
If you each know the
officers you inhabit
then you know
they are equally ready
to give their lives
for this ship.
Free them now
and I will return you
to the moon's surface.
I advise you, Picard,
not to pass our way again.
Picard to Bridge.
RIKER:
Aye, sir.
Our guests will be
leaving shortly.
I need an emergency
medical team down here.
CRUSHER:
On our way, Captain.
Mr. Worf, prepare to
transport these prisoners
down to the
moon's surface.
Gladly, sir.
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45572.1.
Dr. Crusher has examined Troi,
Data and O'Brien.
There seem to be
no residual effects
from their experience.
It was as though
my own consciousness
were pushed to the side.
I was watching
everything happen--
hearing my own voice--
but not being able
to control any of it.
What about the entity
that controlled you?
What were your perceptions
of him?
( sighing )
He was intelligent,
actually.
Thoughtful, in a
ruthless kind of way.
Cold.
Lieutenant,
I must apologize
for my inadvertent
misconduct toward you.
No apology necessary.
Your restraint was
most remarkable.
( sighs )
You have no idea.
How do you feel?
Hungry.
That's a good sign.
Go home.
How do you feel?
I'm just glad
to have you back.
If I could have killed
that thing inside me...
I would have.
I know.
We both know.
( chuckles )
( cooing )