No question about it.
She was bluffing, Worf.
Bluffing is not one of
Counselor Troi's strong suits.
I'm still reading
chlorinide leakage,
but I can't pin it down.
Maybe up here.
It would have been
unwise to call.
Yes, my hand was
not strong enough.
You had jacks
and eights.
She bluffed you
with a pair of sixes.
How did you know what I had?
Let's just say I had
a special insight
into the cards.
Maybe next time
you should bring a deck
that's not transparent
to infrared light.
Not to worry, Worf.
I only peek after
the hand is over.
( sighs )
Still nothing.
I'll get a dynoscan.
We'll try it again.
Commander, here's our latest
reading, should we continue on?
Yes, and if anything changes,
you let me know.
Yes, sir.
( beeping )
( hissing )
( beeping continues )
( beeping gets louder )
WOMAN:
Look out!
Worf!
MAN:
Commander, what happened?
La Forge to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency
in Cargo Bay three.
What happened?
The containers you were
checking fell on you.
You're lucky to be alive.
Doctor,
I will not attempt
to leave Sick Bay
without your approval.
The restraining field
is not necessary.
Worf...
there is
no restraining field.
But I can't move my legs.
I know.
You can't move
because one of the containers
shattered seven
of your vertebrae
and crushed
your spinal cord.
I'm afraid there's no way
we can repair
this kind of injury.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45587.3:
Lieutenant Worf has been
removed from active duty
following a severe injury.
Although a neuro-specialist
has arrived,
Dr. Crusher believes
his paralysis may be permanent.
Welcome to the Enterprise,
Dr. Russell.
I'm Beverly Crusher.
A pleasure.
I have some equipment
aboard the Potemkin.
Would you please have it sent
to one of your Medical Labs?
Of course.
Send it to Med Lab four.
CREWMAN: Yes, Doctor.
Before we get
down to business,
I just wanted to say
that I had the pleasure
of reading your paper
on cybernetic regeneration
recently.
Really? You're the first
person to mention it.
I thought it
was brilliant.
Your ideas on
bioactive interfaces
border on
revolutionary.
It's going to be a genuine
pleasure working with you.
Thank you.
Have you had a chance to review
Worf's case history yet?
Only briefly.
I must admit,
I was a little shocked
to find the state of Klingon
neurological medicine
to be so primitive.
It's a cultural bias.
When I contacted the
Klingon Medical Division,
they informed me
that they usually
let the patient die
in a case like this.
As a result, they've
done almost no research
on neurological trauma.
We'll be in
unchartered waters.
Worf is having a hard time
dealing with his injuries.
He's always been a difficult
patient, but now...
He's a little tough
at first,
but I'm sure
you'll like him after...
Doctor, I know that
as a starship doctor,
you have to maintain
close ties with patients,
but I think it would be best
if I maintain
a discreet distance.
That way I can give you
a completely objective opinion
regarding treatment.
Yes, you're probably right.
Good.
Well, I believe you said
I'd be working in Med Lab four?
Right. This way.
You look pretty good
for someone
who's been eating Sick Bay
food for three days.
Please, sit down, Commander.
Thank you for
agreeing to see me in...
this condition.
Oh, I'm not a Klingon.
I don't think there's any shame
in someone being injured.
I am not merely injured,
Commander.
Dr. Crusher believes
my paralysis to be...
permanent.
I'm sorry.
I have a personal
favor to ask.
Name it.
I want you to assist me
in performing
the Hegh'bat ceremony.
I want you to help me die.
What?
When a Klingon
can no longer stand
and face his enemies
as a warrior,
when he becomes a burden
to his friends and family,
it is time for the Hegh'bat--
time for him to die.
There must be other options.
No, there are not.
I will not live as an object
of pity or shame.
My life as a Klingon is over.
Mr. Worf...
I will not help a friend
commit suicide.
You and I have served
together for many years,
fought side by side.
I know you to be
a brave and honorable man.
If you truly
consider me a friend,
help me now.
Help me end my life
as I have lived it--
with dignity and honor.
Please.
The cortico-spinal
tract has continued
to deteriorate over
the last 72 hours
despite CPK
enzymatic therapy.
What about
alkysine treatment?
Ineffective.
Overdesigned.
Klingon anatomy--
23 ribs, two livers,
eight-chambered heart,
double-lined neural pia mater.
I've never seen
so many unnecessary
redundancies in one body.
Unnecessary?
The Klingons refer to it
as the brak'lul.
Almost every vital function
in their bodies
has a built-in redundancy
in case any primary organ
or system fails.
It's a good design
in theory,
but in practice,
all the extra organs
means just that much more
can go wrong.
Let me show you
something.
I've been experimenting
with DNA-based generators.
This is a genetronic
replicator.
It reads the DNA coding
of damaged organs,
translates that into a specific
set of replicant instructions
and then begins to grow
a replacement.
I've read of some of the
preliminary work you've done.
The early results have been
very encouraging.
Beverly,
the genetronic replicator
can create a completely
new neural conduit
for your Lieutenant Worf.
Replace his entire
spinal column?
Exactly.
Instead of splicing
and pasting together
broken connections like
a couple of glorified tailors,
we create
a new living system.
I had no idea you were already
using this on humanoids.
I haven't been.
This will be the first time.
First time?
I've done dozens
of holo-simulations.
The success rate is up to 37%.
Even a holographic patient
would balk at those odds.
Sooner or later,
it has to be tried
on a living patient.
You're talking
about a spinal column.
Even before
we could replace it,
we have to remove
the existing one,
and we don't know enough about
Klingon neurological medicine
to reattach it.
If something goes wrong,
he'll die.
I agree it has
remarkable potential,
but you're still in the most
preliminary stages of research.
No, I'm afraid I can't
justify the risk to Worf.
We'll have to do with more
conventional approaches.
PICARD: Dr. Crusher,
please report to the Bridge.
On my way.
Doctor, the transport ship
Denver has struck
a gravitic mine left over
from the Cardassian War.
They've sustained
heavy damage.
Their last message said they
were attempting to crash-land
on one of the planets
in the Mericor system.
We should arrive
in just under seven hours.
How many people
were aboard?
The Denver's standard
crew complement is 23,
but they were transporting
517 colonists
to the Beloti sector.
I'll need to convert
all three Shuttle Bays
into emergency
triage centers.
I want all civilians
with medical training
to report for duty.
Make it so.
Captain, may I speak
to you in private?
Of course, Number One.
You have the Bridge,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
I have always tried
to keep an open mind--
not to judge someone else's
culture by my own--
but for me to be
part of this "ceremony"...
I understand
from Dr. Crusher
that Worf will never regain
the use of his legs.
That doesn't mean
that his life is over.
That's a very
human perspective, Will.
For a Klingon
in Worf's position...
his life is over.
I can't accept that.
Will, if you were dying,
if you were terminally ill
with an incurable disease
and facing the remaining
few days of your life in pain--
wouldn't you come to look
on death as a release?
Worf isn't dying
and he is not in pain.
He could lead
a long life...
You and I could learn to live
with a disability like that,
but not Worf.
His life ended when those
containers fell on him.
Now, we don't have
to agree with it,
we don't have to
understand it,
but we do have to
respect his beliefs.
I can respect his beliefs,
but he is asking me
to take an active part
in his committing suicide!
He's asking for your help
because you're his friend.
That means that you're going
to have to make your decision
based on that friendship.
Which leaves me right back
where I started.
Will...
Look, I'm sorry.
I cannot help you
to make this decision.
But I can tell you this:
Klingons choose their friends
with great care.
If he didn't know
he could count on you,
he would never have asked.
Why won't you let me see him?
Alexander, I told you
it's not my decision.
Your father
doesn't want...
I don't believe you!
My father wants to see me!
You're the one keeping me
away from him.
I think you know
that's not true.
Then why can't I see him?
Come here.
He's been injured
and he's embarrassed.
And to have anyone
see him now
would make him
feel worse,
even if it were you.
This is part of that
Klingon stuff, isn't it?
My mother
always said Klingons
had a lot of dumb ideas
about honor.
Alexander,
that Klingon stuff
is very important
to your father.
Well, it isn't
very important to me.
I don't care
about being Klingon.
I just want
to see my father.
It's been a long day.
Why don't you get
ready for bed
and we'll talk about this
again in the morning, hmm?
( door opens, closes )
Alexander is scared,
confused, hurt...
all because his father
is refusing to see him.
You know why I left
those instructions.
Yes, I do.
It's not
the Klingon way, right?
It is a question of honor,
and I would ask that you
respect my wishes
in this matter, Counselor.
All I care about
at this moment
is a little boy
who's terrified
he's going to
lose his father.
( door opens )
Maybe it's time
you stopped lying here
worrying about your honor
and started thinking
about someone else,
like your son.
Would you like us
to come back later?
No, no.
Please come in, Doctor.
This is Dr. Toby Russell.
She's from the Adelman
Neurological Institute.
She specializes in
spinal injuries like yours.
We've discussed a variety
of surgical procedures.
I'm afraid none of them
will repair the spinal cord,
but we have found a way for you
to regain much of your mobility.
We can implant a series of
neural transducers
into your lower torso
and legs.
They're designed to pick up
the electrical impulses
from your brain
and stimulate
the corresponding muscles.
With a little work,
you can eventually regain 60%
to 70% of your motor control.
The first step would be
to fit your legs
with motor-assist units
like this one.
They're a training device.
Once you've mastered
using them,
we can move on
to the implants.
Now, try to move your leg.
No, no.
That's good for a first try.
It will take some time
before you get used
to manipulating...
No!
I will not live like that.
These are very
sophisticated devices.
With enough time,
they will give you...
WORF:
60% of my mobility?
No, I will not be
seen lurching
through corridors like
some half-Klingon machine--
the object of
ridicule and disgust.
Perhaps all this seems
a bit frightening to you now.
I want you to take some time
before making a decision.
Think about it.
There is one other option
I'd like you to consider.
It's called
genetronic replication.
It's still in
the experimental stage,
but if it works,
it will restore virtually
all your mobility
and without the need
for artificial implants.
I thought we had
discussed genetronics.
We did.
I also thought we decided
against recommending it.
You heard him.
He'd rather die than
live with the implants.
I just gave him a better
option than suicide.
He's grasping for straws
and you're giving him one.
Now, instead of dealing
with his paralysis,
he's going to be thinking about
this miracle cure of yours.
There's a real chance
this could work.
And, if it does,
it will be
a major breakthrough
in neurogenics
that will change
a lot of people's lives.
You're using the desperation
of an injured man
as an excuse
to try a procedure
that you couldn't do
under normal circumstances.
I checked with
Starfleet Medical.
They have turned down your
request to test genetronics
on humanoids
three times already.
Are you really
going to hide
behind the rules
of some bureaucracy?
Beverly, your patient's
life is at stake here.
Look, before you
do any of this...
PICARD:
Picard to Dr. Crusher.
Go ahead, Captain.
We've located the survivors
from the Denver.
We're ready down here.
We have triage teams
standing by.
Very well.
We'll begin transporting the
survivors on board immediately.
Bridge out.
Beverly, could you use
an extra pair of hands?
Absolutely.
Father?
Come in, Alexander.
Deanna said you
hurt your back.
That you couldn't walk.
I am still struggling
with my injury.
I was worried about you.
There is much to discuss.
There will be
difficult times ahead.
You must be strong.
I understand.
Good.
As Klingons, we all
must be prepared for...
( grunts )
Father!
Take him away.
Worf, let me help you.
Leave!
Alexander, go on.
It'll be all right.
I'll take care of your father.
( door opens, closes )
WOMAN:
Doctor, please.
MAN:
Hey, easy now.
MAN #2:
With this patient right here?
WOMAN #2:
Yes.
Use this to cauterize
the tissue.
Yes, Doctor.
( patients moaning )
MAN:
Doctor, we need you right now.
WOMAN:
We have to get back in the lab.
WOMAN #2:
I need more help, please.
MAN:
Yes, right here, right here.
WOMAN #2:
Thank you.
MAN #2:
Hold this right...
just like that.
What happened here?
He went into neural
metaphasic shock.
From leporazine?
That's unusual.
He couldn't take leporazine.
His blood pressure
was too low.
I had to try
a different treatment.
A morathial series?
No.
I tried a new rybotherapy
I've been working with.
It's called borathium.
I've had some
very good results.
You used this man to test
one of your theories?
Borathium is decades ahead
of leporazine and morathial.
Morathial would have
saved his life.
His injuries were so severe,
I don't think any conventional
treatment would have saved him.
The point is you didn't even
try standard treatment.
I made the choice
I thought gave him
the best chance of surviving.
Isn't that what you
would have done?
I think you used
this situation
in order to test
one of your theories,
just like you're trying
to do with Worf.
That's what this is
really about, isn't it?
Lieutenant Worf.
I'm offering him a chance
to recover fully--
a chance you can't give him.
What this is about
is the kind of medicine
you seem to practice.
I make no excuses for
my approach to medicine.
I don't like losing a patient
any more than you do,
but I'm looking
down a long road, Doctor.
This man didn't die
for nothing.
The data that I gathered
is invaluable.
It will eventually help
save thousands of lives.
I doubt if that will be
of any comfort to his family.
Let me ask you this.
If, some years from now,
borathium therapy were to save
the life of someone you loved,
would you still condemn me?
I will not be drawn into
a hypothetical argument, Doctor.
Your research
on this ship is over.
You are relieved of all medical
duties until further notice.
Is that clear?
Perfectly.
Doctor, I'm on my way
to look in on your patient.
Be my guest.
Just don't expect
a lot of conversation.
He's in full Klingon mode--
honorable, strong
and closed-minded.
I understand that you've
relieved Dr. Russell of duty.
That's right.
She's irresponsible.
I won't have her practicing
medicine on this ship.
Beverly...
maybe you should consider
letting her go ahead
with this
genetronic procedure.
How can you say that?
She has a theory based on
a little empirical knowledge
and a lot of supposition.
If he can't make
a full recovery...
Worf will kill himself.
Not in my Sick Bay,
he won't.
I'll put him in
a restraining field
and post security
around his door
before I let him
commit suicide.
And how long will you
keep him there?
A week? A month? A year?
If I have to.
Suicide is not an option.
Putting aside for the moment
the fact that a paraplegic
can live a very full life,
there is also
a conventional therapy
that could restore
much of his mobility.
But not all of it.
No, not all of it!
There are some things
I can't fix!
Klingon or no,
he is going to have to
accept his condition.
Beverly, he can't make the
journey you're asking of him.
You want him to go from
contemplating suicide
to accepting his condition
and living with a disability,
but it's too far.
And the road between covers
a lifetime of values...
beliefs.
He can't do it,
Beverly.
But...
perhaps he can come
part of the way.
Maybe he can be persuaded
to forego the ritual
in order to
take the chance
of regaining
the kind of life he needs.
A Klingon may not be good
at accepting defeat,
but he knows
all about taking risks.
The first tenet
of good medicine
is never make
the patient any worse.
Right now, Worf is
alive and functioning.
If he goes into
that operation,
he could come out
a corpse.
And this may not be
good medicine,
but for Worf...
it may be
his only choice.
I am ready, Commander.
I've been studying
this ritual of yours.
Do you know what
I've decided?
I think it's despicable.
I hate everything about it--
casual disregard
for life,
the way it tries
to cloak suicide
in some glorious
notion of honor.
I may have to respect
your beliefs,
but I don't
have to like them.
It is not something
I expect you to understand.
No-- all you really
expect me to do
is bring you the knife,
and then walk away
so you can kill yourself
in peace.
Well...
I'm not going to make it
that easy for you.
It is not easy for me,
but each of us must die
at our own time and my time...
Do you remember Sandoval?
Hit with a disrupter
blast two years ago?
She lived for about a week.
Fang-lee,
Marla Aster,
Tasha Yar?
How many men and women--
how many friends
have we watched die?
I've lost count.
Every one of them--
every single one fought
for life until the very end.
I do not welcome death,
Commander.
Are you sure?
Because I get the sense
you're feeling pretty noble
about this whole thing.
"Look at me.
Aren't I courageous?
Aren't I
an honorable Klingon?"
Let me remind you
of something.
A Klingon does not
put his desires
above those of his family
or his friends.
How many people on this ship
consider you a friend?
How many owe you their lives?
Have you ever thought
about how you've affected
the people around you?
How we might feel
about your dying?
Will you or will you not
help me with the Hegh'bat?
You are my friend...
...and in spite of
everything I've said,
if it were my place,
I would probably help you.
But I've been studying
Klingon ritual and Klingon law
and I've discovered
that it's not my place
to fill that role.
According to tradition,
that honor falls
to a family member,
preferably the oldest son.
That is impossible.
He is a child.
"The son of a Klingon is a man
the day he can first
hold a blade."
True?
Alexander is not fully Klingon.
He is part human.
That's an excuse.
What you really mean
is it would be too hard
to look at your son
and tell him
to bring you the knife,
watch you stab it
into your heart,
then pull the knife
out of your chest
and wipe your blood
on his sleeve.
That's the rite
of death, isn't it?
Well, I'm sorry, Mr. Worf.
I can't help you.
There's only one person
on this ship who can.
You said you
wanted to see me?
I need you to help me.
Anything, Father.
I have taught you about
Klingon customs--
the beliefs which we value.
According to tradition,
I must take my life
after suffering
this kind of injury.
But I have decided
to break with tradition.
I have decided to live.
I'm glad, Father.
I must still undergo
a dangerous operation.
I may still die,
but it will not be
by my own hand.
Return this
to our quarters.
Yes, sir.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental:
After further consultation
with Starfleet Medical
and a great deal
of soul-searching,
I have reluctantly granted
Lieutenant Worf's request
to undergo
the genetronic procedure.
We started doing
multiplications today.
The teacher said I'm faster
than anybody else in my class.
We will speak again soon.
Yes, Father.
If I die...
...he must be cared for.
I'll make sure he reaches
your parents' home safely.
No. They are elderly.
They cannot care
for Alexander.
Counselor,
I have a serious request
to make of you.
Would you consider...
You want me
to raise Alexander?
I have come to have
a great respect for you, Deanna.
You have been most helpful
in guiding me
since Alexander's arrival.
I can't imagine anyone
who would be a better
parent to my son.
If it is too much to ask...
I'd be honored.
I am ready.
RUSSELL:
Focus the drechtal beams
on the anterior
and posterior spinal roots.
DR. CRUSHER:
Focused.
RUSSELL:
Initiate.
All neural connections below
the first cervical vertebrae
have been separated.
Microtome.
I'm severing the brain stem...
now.
Cerebral cortex placed
on life support
at 0831 hours--
three hours
26 minutes remaining until onset
of primary brain dysfunction.
Okay, let's remove
the support frame.
Exoscalpel.
I've notified Starfleet that our
survey of sector 37628
will be delayed by at least
a week while we drop off
the survivors
from the Denver.
Good.
I understand
from Mr. La Forge
that there's a minor fluctuation
in the starboard warp coil.
I've scheduled
a stress simulation routine
for this afternoon
to check it out.
Has there been any word?
No.
DR. CRUSHER: Preliminary
genetronic scans are complete.
( beeping )
Initiating DNA sequencer.
Reading the initial sequences
at ten to the ninth base
pairs per second.
Once we're past
the first two levels,
we'll begin
the encoding sequence.
Increase TCH levels to...
( alarm sounds )
What's happened?
The scanner is having trouble
reading the Klingon
dorsal root ganglia.
Did this show up
in your simulations?
Yes, but I thought I made
sufficient adjustments.
Bring me
the detronal scanner.
I can scan
the ganglia manually.
It will just take
a little longer.
One hour, 43 minutes until
primary brain dysfunction.
Retract the paraspinal muscle.
Got it.
Watch the proximal
nerve endings.
I see them.
Make sure the cranial
segment is at least
15 centimeters
from the brain stem.
I'm reading a slight fluctuation
in the isocortex.
20 CC's inaprovaline.
Okay.
Release the retractors
on the paraspinal.
How much longer can we
keep him on life support?
27 minutes.
Cover.
Close, please.
Ready.
RUSSELL:
Tissue growth proceeding
at anticipated rates.
No initial signs
of rejection.
Okay. Ready.
Terminate life support.
Life support disengaged.
RUSSELL:
Neural connections
appear stable.
Looking good so far.
( alarm sounding )
Fluctuations
in the isocortex.
40 CC's inaprovaline.
Synaptic response falling.
BP dropping.
Now 60/40.
VeK'tal response
is falling rapidly.
Increase oxygen mixture
to 95%.
Beginning direct
synaptic stimulation.
Respiration is
shallow and rapid.
No response in the isocortex.
75 CC's inaprovaline.
Heart rate is erratic.
He's going into
cardiac arrest.
All right, let's go
to chloromydride-- 15 CC's.
We're losing him.
No BP, no pulse.
Brain activity?
Showing no higher
brain functions.
Okay. 25 CC's cordrazine.
That'll kill him.
Looks like we've done
a pretty good job of that
already, Doctor.
No BP, no pulse.
No activity in the isocortex.
Cortical stimulator.
Now.
( electricial surge )
( erratic beeping )
( flatline tone )
Again.
( flatline tone continues )
( electrical surge )
Again.
Doctor...
All right.
Make a note in the log.
Death occurred at 1240 hours.
It was all going so well.
No anomalies
during replication,
no initial rejection...
No.
Alexander,
I am so sorry.
I want to see him.
Alex...
No!
I want to see him.
Activate biomonitors.
25 CC's polyadrenaline.
What's going on?
I'm not sure,
but if I'm right,
one of those unnecessary
redundancies...
Doctor!
DR. CRUSHER:
I don't believe it.
Begin cardio-aid
and ventilation.
That's amazing.
There must be a backup for
his synaptic functions as well.
Vital signs
are stabilizing.
DR. CRUSHER:
Begin rybosomatic therapy.
Increase oxygen mixture
to 90%.
Let's prepare a thalamic
booster series.
Well, I'd say your patient's
recovery is going well.
You aren't even
going to acknowledge
what I did for him,
are you?
You just can't admit
that it was my research
that made this possible.
I am delighted that Worf
is going to recover.
You gambled, he won.
Not all of your patients
are so lucky.
You scare me, Doctor.
You risk your patients' lives
and justify it
in the name of research.
Genuine research
takes time.
Sometimes a lifetime
of painstaking,
detailed work in order
to get any results.
Not for you.
You take shortcuts,
right through
living tissue.
You put your research ahead
of your patients' lives,
and as far as
I'm concerned,
that's a violation
of our most sacred trust.
I'm sure your work
will be hailed
as a stunning
breakthrough.
Enjoy your laurels, Doctor.
I'm not sure I could.
( Worf grunting )
DR. CRUSHER: This is going
to take time, Worf.
Your muscles are still
sorting out their new signals.
Don't rush it.
( groaning )
Alexander, Alexander,
remember what
we talked about?
Your father wants to
do this by himself.
It's all right, Counselor.
I would appreciate
some help from my son.
We will work together.
Yes, sir.