Captain's Log,
Stardate 45614.6.
We have been contacted
by an androgynous race
called the J'naii
to investigate
the mysterious disappearance
of one of their shuttlecraft.
Captain, we are approaching
the designated coordinates.
On screen.
PICARD:
Long-range scan, Mr. Data.
Sensors find no evidence
of the shuttle
anywhere within the star system.
It couldn't have traveled
outside the system.
Mr. Data, reconfigure
high-resolution sweep.
Radius one million kilometers.
Check for any debris.
Scans find no debris
within that radius.
I don't understand it.
A shuttle doesn't
simply vanish.
There has to be an explanation.
DATA:
Captain...
I'm detecting
an unusual reading.
It appears to be a neutrino
emission with no visible source.
Explanation.
DATA: I have none, sir.
I recommend we launch a probe.
Make it so.
Probe is launched.
Sensors show no evidence
of any unusual phenomenon.
The probe is
no longer transmitting.
J'NAII:
What happened?
Where did it go?
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The sudden disappearance
of our probe
suggests that we may have found
the first instance of what
is called "null space--"
an anomaly which, until now,
had been only theoretical.
Commander Riker has been
working around the clock
with a team
of J'naii specialists
to formalize this hypothesis.
During the creation
of a star system,
when clouds of interstellar dust
and gas coalesce,
turbulent regions
of magnetic
and gravitational fields
may develop.
If certain conditions occur
these fields
can condense
into abnormal
pockets of space.
We think
your system contains
one of these
null pockets.
If we're right,
the pocket would absorb
electromagnetic energy from
anything that entered it.
J'NAII:
Like a shuttlecraft.
RIKER:
Or a probe.
Making them powerless.
But, outside the pocket
all the energy
is bent around it,
making it
naturally cloaked.
That's why we
cannot see it
and our sensors
cannot read it.
Is the shuttle still there?
RIKER:
We think so.
The shuttle probably was not
able to sustain its energy
but, other than that,
it wouldn't be damaged.
Since our
shuttles carry
plestorene-based
backup systems
we think life-support
would sustain
for as long
as ten days.
Then perhaps our crew
has survived.
We could send in
one of our own shuttles,
but its energy
would also be absorbed.
Our chief engineer
is working on a way
to maintain
the power reserves
long enough
to rescue your crew.
Commander...
we're grateful for your help.
Whatever resources
we can provide are yours.
I've been thinking.
When the time comes,
I would like to pilot
the shuttle.
It's a Starfleet craft.
I cannot ask you
to put yourself
in danger
to rescue our crew.
You can't pilot a shuttle
you're not familiar with.
I happen to be
a good pilot.
a good pilot, too,
and I know my way around
the Starfleet shuttle.
So, what if we team up?
When can we go over
the shuttle flight operations?
Right now.
SOREN:
Is this the one?
RIKER: This is it.
Short-range craft.
Two 1250-millicochrane
warp engines.
Looks like
microfusion thrusters?
Right.
Armament?
None, usually, but this
one's been equipped
with two type-4
phaser emitters.
We'll use those to
chart the null space.
Chart it?
Mr. La Forge wants
to get an idea
of the size
of the pocket.
He thinks the rate
of energy absorption's
linked to its size.
I'm not sure
how we'd go about
mapping something
we can't see.
Well, that's where
the emitters come in.
We shoot out a series of
photon pulses into the pocket
and chart where
each one disappears.
From that, we should get
a fairly complete outline.
Let's have a look
at the controls.
Later, we'll try
a flight simulation.
Right now, let's
do a systems review.
I'll talk you through it.
Let me try it.
Propulsion system,
transfer conduits...
where's the schematic
reactor assembly?
Oh, there it is.
Engine nacelles.
There's nothing here
that's unfamiliar.
Navigational deflector,
redundant.
Graviton polarity
source generators...
You handle these
controls like you
grew up in a shuttle.
I did.
My parents were pilots.
I was flying with them
before I could walk.
As soon as I was old enough,
I entered flight school.
Krite was my instructor.
He had a good student.
"He?" Commander,
there are no he's or she's
in a species
without gender.
Okay. For two days,
I've been trying to
construct sentences
without personal pronouns.
Now I give up.
What should I use, "it"?
To us, that's rude.
We use a pronoun
that is neutral.
I do not think
there is really a translation.
Well, then I'll just
have to muddle through.
So, forgive me if the stray
"he" or "she" slips by, okay?
Well, if that's
the systems review,
I don't see any problem.
What's next?
Lunch.
Thank you.
What is it?
Split pea soup.
It's my father's recipe.
I had it programmed
into the replicators.
Well?
Unusual...
but I think I like it.
It's very healthy.
Helps to keep you warm
on cold Alaskan nights.
We prefer to stay warm
by sleeping with a friend.
I see.
Not to mate.
Just to sleep together,
for warmth.
That still sounds better
than pea soup.
We are puzzling
to you, aren't we?
A little.
It's hard to grasp
the idea of no gender.
It is just as hard
for us to understand...
the strange division
in your species.
Males and females.
You are male?
Mm-hmm.
Tell me about males.
What is it makes you
different from females?
( sighing )
"Snips and snails
and puppy dog tails."
You have a dog's tail?
It's an old
nursery rhyme.
Girls are made
from sugar and spice
and boys are made
from snips and... snails.
That makes it sound
better to be female.
It's an old-fashioned way
of looking at the sexes--
not to say that there's no
real difference between them.
Physically, men are bigger,
stronger in the upper body.
We have different
sexual organs.
Men can't bear young.
And what about feelings
or emotional attitudes?
Are they different?
Most people think so,
but that's
the kind of question
it would take
a lifetime to answer.
Let me ask you.
What's it like
on a planet
where the people
have no gender?
I'm afraid
I don't understand.
Well...
Who leads when you
dance, if you dance?
We do...
and whosever taller leads.
Without the battle
of the sexes,
you probably don't have
as many arguments.
Just because
we don't have gender
doesn't mean
we don't have conflicts.
We are very
strong-minded.
We love a good fight.
From the sound
of it, there's not
that much difference
between our species.
Maybe not.
What kind of... woman
do you find attractive?
I like one who's intelligent
and sure of herself...
who I can talk with
and get something back.
But the most important
thing of all?
She has to laugh at my jokes.
Tell me...
is that the kind of woman
that all human males prefer?
Not at all.
Some like quiet,
demure women.
Others prefer
a lot of energy.
Some only respond
to physical attractiveness.
Others couldn't
care less.
There are no rules.
You make it sound
very complex.
Believe me, it is.
Well, perhaps
it is that complexity
which makes
the differences in the sexes
so... interesting.
Good evening, Commander.
Good evening.
Please take my place,
Krite.
I have to be going.
Thank you for going over
the flight protocols, Commander.
It was very helpful.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Commander Riker
and the J'naii pilot
have set out to chart
the null space pocket.
If they are successful,
we can then proceed
with a rescue attempt.
I've illuminated
Delta-Four grid map.
We'll start there
and expand.
Stand by
forward phaser array.
The pulse vanished
at Delta 4.2 by .3.
Firing second burst.
J'NAII:
Delta 4.4 by .5.
RIKER:
This is working.
Initiating computer
task handoff.
Commander, tell me
about your sexual organs.
Uh...
Is that an uncomfortable subject
for humans?
No, but it doesn't tend to be
a topic of casual conversation.
I'm interested
in your mating practices.
What is involved with two sexes?
Correcting course--
021,
mark 0.
Mating.
Right.
Well, it's pretty simple.
The men inseminate the women,
and the women carry the baby.
Our fetuses are incubated
in fibrous husks
which the parents inseminate.
From what we know
of other species,
our method is less risky,
and less painful.
And less enjoyable.
Less enjoyable?
For humans...
the sexual act brings
a closeness and intimacy.
It can be
a very pleasurable experience.
Inseminating a husk...
That's just the last step.
Mating is a long ritual for us,
full of variety and invention.
I assure you...
It is extremely pleasurable.
I'm picking up
neutrino emission
from within
the null space.
That may be coming
from our shuttle.
I'll note
these coordinates.
I wonder.
RIKER:
What?
If a human and J'naii
would be sexually compatible.
I don't know.
Of course,
it would never be permitted.
Why not?
The idea of gender--
it is offensive to my people.
You see, long ago,
we had two sexes, as you do.
But we evolved
into a higher form.
I don't mean to sound insulting,
but on my planet,
we have been taught
that gender is...
primitive.
Primitive?
Less evolved.
Maybe so.
But sometimes,
there's a lot to be said
for an experience
that's primitive.
Delta-Five grid map
is fully plotted.
Adjusting course--
029 mark 0.
The port engine's down!
Reducing power
to the starboard nacelle.
That's not enough.
I have to activate
the maneuvering thrusters.
Thrusters aren't responding.
I'll try to reroute
the firing sequence.
Inertial dampeners
are failing!
Hang on!
LA FORGE:
Enterprise to shuttle.
Do you read me?
Affirmative.
We've lost an engine.
We'll try to get
a tractor beam on you.
The sooner the better.
Enterprise,
we have an injury.
Transport Soren
directly to Sick Bay.
Right away, Commander.
It's just
a minor concussion.
You're going to be fine.
This will reduce
the inflammation.
Doctor?
You are female?
Yes.
Forgive me.
I do not mean to be rude,
but I'm curious.
What is it like?
Well, it's...
it's just the way I am.
I've never really thought
about what it's like.
I notice you tend
to have longer hair.
Hmm.
And you arrange it
more elaborately.
And you apply color
to your bodies.
Color?
You put color on your mouths
and your eyes,
your cheeks,
and your fingernails.
The men don't.
That's true.
Then it is up to women
to attract the men?
Oh, no.
Men want to be
attractive, too, believe me.
They just go about it
differently.
No color.
They like to pretend
they're not doing anything
to attract a woman,
even when it's the most
important thing on their minds.
This is very confusing.
Then...
are women considered
more superior?
Or the men?
Neither.
In the past...
women were often considered
weak and inferior.
But...
that hasn't been true
for a long time.
Will...
your copilot is
going to be fine.
The injury
was minor.
Glad to hear it.
I'm afraid you're not
rid of me yet, Commander.
I will be able
to complete
the mission.
I'm glad
you're feeling better.
What happened?
What made the shuttle
go into a spin?
The port nacelle
must have nipped
one of the protrusions
from the null pocket
and shut it down.
Are we still on
schedule, then?
That depends
on how you're doing.
I'm fine. We should go
check the port engine.
Whoa.
I think we should get
the doctor's opinion first.
Doctor?
I don't see any problem.
But if you feel any symptoms--
headache, dizziness-- come back.
You have my word.
All right.
This hand, the game
is "Federation Day."
What is that?
Well, the Federation
was founded in 2161.
So...
twos, sixes and aces
are wild.
That is a woman's game.
Oh? Why is that?
All those wild cards.
They support a weak hand.
A man's game
has no wild cards.
Let me get this straight.
You're saying
it's a woman's game
because women are weak
and need more help?
Yes.
And just this afternoon,
I was insisting
to one of the J'naii
that those attitudes
were but a distant memory.
The J'naii...
they bother me.
Why, Worf?
Well, they
just do.
They're all alike.
No males, no females.
Well, I'm sure we're
just as strange to them.
Well, one of them seems to be
overcoming the differences,
at least in regards
to one of us.
What are you saying,
Doctor?
I could be wrong,
but I get
the definite impression
that Soren is attracted
to Commander Riker.
A human and a J'naii?
Impossible.
Why?
Good question.
Worf?
With all these wild cards
it is difficult to know
what is exactly in my hand.
However, I will
open with 50.
The portable transporter
array is in.
When we get into
the null space
we'll need to initialize it
before we can transport
the J'naii crew
onto this shuttle.
But there should still
be enough power left
to beam us all back
to the Enterprise.
Is the buffer field
generator installed?
Not yet. Geordi thinks
that'll be ready
by 0800 hours tomorrow.
But before that,
we should see if we can
balance this engine.
Can you access
the starboard manifold thrust?
There.
Set the arc at 6.3.
I'll optimize the plasma flow.
Commander...
I'd like
to tell you something.
Something that's
not easy to say.
What's that?
I find you attractive.
I am taking a terrible risk
telling you that.
It means revealing
something to you,
something that, if it
were known on my planet
would be very dangerous
for me.
Occasionally,
among my people...
there are a few
who are born different--
who are throwbacks from the era
when we all had gender.
Some have strong
inclinations to maleness
and some have urges
to be female.
I am one of the latter.
I have to admit, I had
a feeling you were different.
I was hoping you would.
But in front of Krite
and the others,
I must be careful
not to reveal myself.
Why?
On our world,
these feelings
are forbidden.
Those who are discovered
are shamed and ridiculed.
And only by undergoing
psychotectic therapy
and having all elements
of gender eliminated
can they be accepted
into society again.
Those of us who
have these urges
live secret and guarded lives.
We seek each other out...
always hiding...
always terrified
of being discovered.
How long have you known
that you were like this?
I have known
I was different all my life,
but I did not know how
or why until I was older.
And when you realized--
what then?
I remember
when I was very young,
before I knew what I was,
there was a rumor
at my school
that one of the students
preferred a gender--
in that case, male.
The children started
making fun of him
and every day,
they were more cruel.
They could tell
he was afraid,
and somehow, that seemed
to encourage them.
One morning in class,
he appeared, bleeding
and in ripped clothes.
He said he had fallen down.
And, of course, the school
authorities found out
and took him away
and gave him
psychotectic treatments.
When he came back...
he stood in front
of the whole school
and told us how happy he was,
now that he had been cured.
After that, I realized
how dangerous it was
to be different.
And once I got older
and knew what I was,
I was terrified.
I have had to live
with that fear ever since.
Do you have...
relationships with others?
Yes...
with those who have
discovered they are male.
I have had
to live a life
of pretense and lies
but with you,
I can be honest.
Please, don't
say anything.
Just think about it.
That's it, Commander.
Everything checks out.
The energy buffer
is installed and functioning.
I estimate it should
reduce the power drain
to your systems
by about 40%.
Any guess
how long we'll have?
Let's just say you don't
want to waste any time
once you get in there.
You'll have to give him
continuous readouts
on energy consumption.
I can't even predict
if the drain
will be at a constant rate.
I understand.
Then that's it.
Commander, I'll monitor you
as far as I can
but, once you get inside
that pocket, you're on your own.
We don't have any
idea what condition
the shuttlecraft
crew is in,
so we'll all beam
directly to sick bay.
I'll notify Dr. Crusher
to be standing by.
La Forge to bridge.
PICARD:
Picard here.
We're ready to initiate
shuttle prelaunch sequence.
Proceed, Mr. Data.
Initiating
prelaunch sequence.
RIKER:
Request flight clearance.
Clearance is granted.
The shuttle is
underway, sir.
Good hunting,
Commander.
RIKER:
Thank you, sir.
See you for dinner.
Heading confirmed.
Energy readings
are normal
with power reserves
stabilized at 100%.
Acknowledged.
It's dead ahead.
Approximately
50 kilometers.
Riker to Enterprise.
We're taking her in.
Power reserves
are down to 84%.
Look.
Try hailing them.
Calling the Taris Murn.
Do you read me?
( console beeping )
I'm getting sensor readings.
They're unconscious,
but they're alive.
Stand by.
I'm going to transport
them over here.
Power reserves at 68%
and dropping.
( sighs )
The null space
must be affecting
the annular
confinement beam.
We used ten megajoules
with that attempt.
We're down to 34%
of reserves.
We can give it one more try.
More than that,
we won't have enough power
to get ourselves out of here.
They need
medical attention quickly.
Okay, stand by to transport
to the Enterprise.
Here we go.
Energy consumption?
We're down to nine percent.
We don't have enough
to get back.
If we just sit here, we'll
lose all of our systems
within an hour,
including life-support.
Okay, I'm rerouting
the propulsion system
to the transporter.
Rechannel
the navigation systems.
Let's transfer
every microjoule
of energy we've got.
Sensors... life-support.
This might give us
one last shot.
But if we use
an energy shift
of that size, it will overload
the phase compensators.
The shuttle...
...will explode.
But if we stay here,
we're dead, anyway.
Maximum energy levels,
five seconds.
( consoles beeping )
See you in a minute.
CRUSHER:
They've been
oxygen deprived.
But there doesn't seem
to be any significant damage.
Prepare some dexalin.
Yes, Doctor.
Commander...
Thank you.
Your colleague, Soren,
was very helpful.
Captain, would you all join us
this evening?
We would like to express
our gratitude.
We'd be happy to.
Noor will be eager
for a firsthand report.
We should return
to the surface.
I will see you later
tonight, Commander.
( conversation and laughter )
There you are,
Commander.
I wondered
what had happened
to our guest of honor.
I just needed some air.
I can only take so much
of those social functions,
and then I need
to breathe a little.
I would think you had attended
so many affairs like this
that it had
become second nature to you.
I was raised outdoors.
I've never been very...
comfortable in crowded rooms.
What do you think
of our planet?
Isn't it beautiful?
Yes, it is.
It's beautiful.
We have many varieties
of plant life.
Perhaps you would like
to inspect some of them?
Yes, I would.
I've always been interested
in exobotany.
Please, let me
take you on a tour.
Thank you.
It's kind of you.
One of my favorites
is this menellen tree.
The leaves first
turn pure white
and then blue when
the weather gets cold.
This is called
a falla bush.
It produces
a fragrant flower
on only one day
of the year.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45620.4.
In the hope that a detailed map
of the null space
will prevent
the loss of other ships,
we remain in orbit of J'naii,
charting the anomaly.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Will.
What's all this?
Wonderful things.
My mother sent me a box
that belonged to one
of my father's ancestors.
It was stored on Earth
and just recently turned up.
Do you know who any
of these people are?
No.
Some of the pictures
have names on,
but most of them don't.
I look at these faces,
and I wonder who they are
and if they could be
related to me.
Well, this one looks
like you.
Deanna...
I have something
on my mind.
I had to see you.
Has something happened?
I've met someone--
someone who's becoming
important to me.
Soren.
Yes.
You're my friend,
and I thought...
I don't know,
I thought I should tell you.
I'm glad you did.
Nothing will change
between us, will it?
Of course it will.
All relationships are
constantly changing.
But we'll still be friends,
maybe better friends.
You're a part of my life,
and I'm a part of yours.
That much will
always be true.
Hello.
I'm here to see Soren.
I know.
We had an appointment.
We were going to discuss...
I don't think so,
Commander.
Excuse me?
We know about the two of you.
We know what you're doing.
Where is Soren?
And we're going to make sure
it doesn't happen again.
Answer me-- where is Soren?
In custody.
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
The hell there isn't.
You are aware of
the charges against you?
Yes.
Do you intend
to dispute them?
Well?
What is your response?
Commander Riker,
these proceedings
are closed to everyone...
I think I just
opened them.
Sir, this is
a private matter.
We are grateful
for your recent help
but that gives you no right
to interfere
with our personal
concerns.
I just want you to know
what really happened.
It was all my fault.
I was attracted to Soren.
I pursued.
I insisted.
I didn't understand
your ways until she
explained them to me
and rejected me.
Nothing happened
between us.
I ask your
forgiveness.
I behaved...
inappropriately.
Is this true?
No.
Soren.
I am tired of lies.
I am female.
I was born that way.
I have had those feelings...
those longings...
all of my life.
It is not unnatural.
I am not sick because
I feel this way.
I do not need
to be helped.
to be cured.
What I need...
and what all of those
who are like me need...
is your understanding...
and your compassion.
We have not
injured you in any way.
And yet we are scorned
and attacked.
And all because
we are different.
What we do is no different
from what you do.
We talk...
and laugh.
We complain about work.
And we wonder about growing old.
We talk about
our families
and we worry about the future.
And we cry with each other
when things seem hopeless.
All of the loving things
that you do with each other--
that is what we do.
And for that,
we are called misfits
and deviants
and criminals.
What right do you have
to punish us?
to change us?
What makes you think
you can dictate
how people love each other?
I congratulate you, Soren.
Your decision
to admit your perversion
makes it much more likely
that we can help you.
Wait, wait, wait.
You don't have to do this.
Commander...
Let me take her with me.
She could go back
to the Enterprise.
We would give her asylum.
You would never
have to see her again.
That would solve the problem,
wouldn't it?
You'd be rid of her!
She would never be able
to influence anyone again.
Commander...
after Soren's diatribe,
you must think that we are
a cruel, repressive people.
Nothing could be further
from the truth.
I'm just trying
to find a solution
that would satisfy everyone.
We're concerned
about our citizens.
We take our obligations
to them seriously.
Soren is sick, and sick people
want to get well.
Did it occur to you
that she might like
to stay the way she is?
No, you don't understand.
We have a very high success rate
in treating deviants like this.
And, without exception,
they become happier people
after their treatment,
and grateful
that we care enough
to cure them.
You see, Commander,
on this world
everyone wants
to be normal.
She is!
Take Soren to quarters.
Treatment will begin tomorrow.
RIKER:
Don't do this.
Soren!
No more, Commander.
( crowd murmuring )
Riker to Enterprise.
One to transport.
I can't just
leave her there.
They'll give her
these psychotectic treatments.
I don't know
what to do!
Well, I could
talk to Noor.
Perhaps there's a way
to work something out.
Sir, their minds
are set.
They don't want to hear
another alternative.
Then I'm not sure
that there's much
that we can do.
There has to be.
My relationship with Soren
is not trivial.
She's very important to me.
It's my fault
that this happened.
I have to help her.
Will, if you're
here for sanction
to take matters
into your own hands
I can't give it to you.
I know that,
but I have to do something.
Interfering in the internal
affairs of the J'naii
is prohibited by
the Prime Directive.
I'm aware of that.
If you violate
it, you may be
jeopardizing
your career.
Starfleet doesn't
take these matters
lightly, Will, and
I can't defend you
if you go too far.
Do you understand?
You've made yourself
very clear, sir.
Don't put at risk
everything you've worked for.
Thank you.
May I be excused now?
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Who is it?
Lieutenant Worf.
Come in.
Commander, I have the plan
for deploying warning buoys
around the null space.
Fine, leave it.
I'll take a look at it later.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
You're dismissed.
Commander, I am aware
of what transpired
on the planet's surface.
Are you, by any chance,
considering an...
unannounced visit?
I will go with you.
Lieutenant...
Sir, you are
my commanding officer.
If you order me
to stay on board, I will obey,
but I ask you
not to give that order.
A warrior does not let
a friend face danger alone.
RIKER:
Something's happening.
They're leaving.
( murmuring voices )
Okay.
Excuse me.
I need to speak to her
alone for a moment.
( grunting )
Wait!
Don't worry.
We'll be out of
here in a minute.
Please don't.
All right.
We're almost there.
You cannot do this.
I won't let them hurt you.
You'll be safe on
the Enterprise.
I am so sorry.
It was my fault
that you got involved
in all this.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Everything's
going to be fine.
No.
It is not.
What are you
talking about?
It was all a mistake...
and I should have realized it
from the beginning.
What?
That I was sick.
I had these terrible urges
and that is why
I reached out to you.
But it was wrong,
and I see that now.
I do not understand
how I could have done
what I did.
Maybe Dr. Crusher
could treat you
and bring you back
to the way you were.
Why would I want that?
Soren...
I love you.
I'm sorry.
How long to the Phelan system,
Mr. Data?
At warp six,
53 hours, sir.
Commander.
Captain.
Starfleet has sent a message
asking us to proceed
to the Phelan system
to negotiate
a trade agreement.
Yes, sir.
I didn't know when to tell
them we would be there.
Is our business
with the J'naii finished?
Finished, sir.
Very well.
Ensign, take us out of orbit.
Set a course for
the Phelan system.
Warp six.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
PICARD: Engage.