Damage report!
Casualty reports coming in
from all over the ship!
The starboard nacelle
has sustained a direct impact.
We are venting
drive plasma.
Initiating
emergency core shutdown!
Inertial dampers failing.
We're losing attitude control.
This is the bridge. All hands
to emergency escape pods!
Core shutdown
is unsuccessful.
We are losing antimatter
containment.
We've got to eject
the core!
Ejection systems
off-line.
Core breach
is imminent.
All hands abandon ship!
Repeat, all hands aban...
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45652.1.
The Enterprise has entered
an area of space
known as the Typhon Expanse.
We are the first
Starfleet vessel
to chart
this unexplored region.
Sometimes I wonder
if he's stacking the deck.
I assure you, Commander,
the cards are
sufficiently randomized.
I hope so.
Eight.
Ace.
Queen.
The dealer receives a four.
No bet.
Ten.
Seven.
No help there.
Pair of ladies
for the doctor.
Dealer receives a nine.
Doctor?
May I remind you,
since you show the highest hand
you control the next bet.
Thank you, Data.
I bet ten.
Worf?
Jack.
Four.
Deuce.
Six.
Twenty.
Your 20, and 50 more.
Fifty?!
( muttering )
I'm in.
I will also see the bet.
Seven and a possible straight
for Commander Riker.
Jack. Still no help
for the Klingon.
Eight.
Nine for the dealer.
Twenty.
Too rich for my blood.
Your 20.
100 more.
Fold.
Two hundred.
Your two, and 300 more.
He does not have a straight.
Well, we'll soon
find out, won't we?
Let's see your cards.
Take it.
( squeals )
How'd you know
I was bluffing?
I just had a feeling.
I guess it's better
to be lucky than good.
It's the way your left eyebrow
raises when you're bluffing.
Just kidding, Commander.
Ogawa to Dr. Crusher.
Go ahead.
Commander La Forge needs you
in sick bay.
On my way.
At first, I thought the
catwalk was spinning.
As it turns out,
it was me.
Luckily, Ensign Fletcher
was there to grab me.
It's a long way down
to the bottom of the warp core.
You have all the symptoms
of an inner ear infection.
That would explain
the dizziness and
the headaches.
But there's no
physical evidence.
My guess is, you've
been working too hard.
( sighing )
Well, I have been putting
a lot of extra hours
on this Typhon Expanse project.
I'll give you 20
cc's of vertazine.
That should clear
up the dizziness,
but finding time to
relax is up... to you.
What? What is it?
Geordi, have you had
these symptoms before?
No.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm positive.
Why?
It's funny.
I feel like
we've discussed this before
and I remember giving you
a hypospray for dizziness.
Well, I've never had
these symptoms before today
so you must be thinking
about another patient.
No.
I'm sure it was you.
( sighing ):
Well, try to
get some rest
and stay away
from high places
for a few days,
just in case.
Thanks, Doc.
Good night.
( Beverly humming melody )
( humming continues )
( sighs )
( cacophonous voices
murmur indistinctly )
( voices growing louder )
( glass shatters )
As you can see,
the Typhon Expanse is huge.
If we want to chart
the most remote star system
we'll have to launch
a probe within the
next few hours.
Fine. What about
the luminosity studies?
Uh, that may
pose a problem.
How so?
The flux spectrometers are
still down for realignment.
I thought they were supposed
to be back on line yesterday.
They were, until
the stellar dynamics lab decided
they needed to install
new modules.
I recommend we use a
graviton polarimeter.
It will perform a
similar function.
Make it so, Mr. Data.
Captain, I have something
I'd like to report.
Yes, Doctor?
I heard voices
in my room last night.
I was alone, so at
first I thought
I was imagining things.
But this morning,
ten other people reported
hearing voices
at the same time as I did.
What were the voices saying?
I couldn't make them out.
Data, did the sensors pick up
anything unusual last night?
No anomalous readings
were reported.
When we're through here,
recheck the sensor logs.
Aye, sir.
Counselor?
I sensed nothing unusual
last night.
Maybe it's a problem
with the com system.
WORF:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
We are getting unusual readings
20,000 kilometers
off the starboard bow.
On our way.
Report.
RO:
Sensors didn't detect
the phenomenon
until we were almost
on top of it, sir.
It is a highly
localized distortion
of the space-time
continuum.
On screen.
Back us off, Ensign.
Nice and slow.
Aye, sir.
Captain, maneuvering thrusters
are not responding.
The distortion field
is fluctuating.
All main systems
just went down.
Power levels are
dropping rapidly.
Red alert.
There is an energy buildup
in the distortion field.
We have to get
out of here now.
DATA:
Captain, something
is emerging.
Shields up.
Evasive maneuver.
Shields inoperative.
The helm's
not responding.
The vessel is on
a collision course.
Impact
in 36 seconds.
Hail them.
No response.
Suggestions?
Decompress
main shuttle bay.
The explosive reaction
may kick us out of the way.
Captain, I suggest we use
the tractor beam
to alter the other
ship's trajectory.
Mr. Worf, make it so.
Engaging tractor beam.
Damage report!
Casualty reports coming in
from all over the ship!
The starboard nacelle
has sustained a direct impact.
Venting drive plasma.
Initiating emergency
core shutdown!
Inertial dampers failing.
We're losing
attitude control.
This is the bridge.
All hands to emergency
escape pods!
The core shutdown
was unsuccessful.
We are losing
antimatter containment.
We've got to eject
the engine core!
Ejection systems
are off-line.
Core breach
is imminent.
All hands abandon ship!
Repeat, all hands abandon...
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45652.1.
The Enterprise
has entered an area of space
known as the Typhon Expanse.
We are the first
Starfleet vessel
to chart
this unexplored region.
Sometimes I wonder
if he's stacking the deck.
I assure you,
Commander,
the cards have been
sufficiently randomized.
I hope so.
Eight.
Ace.
Queen.
The dealer receives
a four.
No bet.
DATA:
Ten.
Seven.
No help there.
Pair of ladies
for the Doctor.
Dealer receives
a nine.
Doctor?
May I remind you
since you show the highest hand,
you control the next bet.
WORF:
Is there something
wrong, Doctor?
No.
Um, I'll bet ten.
DATA:
Jack.
Four.
Deuce.
Six.
Twenty.
Your 20...
and I'll raise you 50.
You're going to call
my bluff, aren't you?
I think I'll quit
while I'm ahead.
How did you know
I was going to call your bluff?
I just had a feeling.
Me, too.
Ogawa to Dr. Crusher.
Go ahead.
Commander La Forge needs you
in sick bay.
On my way.
At first, I thought the
catwalk was spinning.
As it turns out,
it was me.
I was lucky Ensign Fletcher
was there to grab me.
It's a long way down
to the bottom of
the warp core.
You have all the symptoms
of an inner ear infection.
That would explain
the headaches and the dizziness.
But there's no physical...
What?
What is it?
Geordi, have you ever had
these symptoms before?
Come to think of it,
I think I have.
Do you recall when?
No, I don't.
We've had
this discussion before
and I know I've given you
this examination.
Let's check the medical logs.
You've been treated
several times
for headaches
related to your VISOR
but I read no mention
of dizziness.
Must be deja vu.
Both of us?
About the same thing?
( humming )
( voices murmur indistinctly )
( glass shatters )
( murmuring stops )
Crusher to Picard.
Yes, Doctor?
Do you have a minute, Jean-Luc?
My Aunt Adele cured
a lot of sleepless nights
with this steamed milk.
Thank you.
Mmm. Nutmeg.
Whenever I get insomnia
I try to perfect
the recipe.
It was the eeriest feeling.
When the glass broke
it triggered the sensation
even more intensely
that I'd done it
all before.
You know...
earlier, I was reading
this book
and I had
the distinct feeling
that I'd read
certain paragraphs before.
But I assumed that I'd
read the book years ago
and I'd forgotten.
I've had this feeling
for hours...
and then the voices.
Well...
( sighs )
...it could be nothing more than
the result of a sleepless night
but let's be sure.
Have Data and Geordi run
a ship-wide diagnostic
concentrating
on the time and place
when you heard the voices.
And we'll discuss the results
tomorrow at 0700 hours.
Thank you...
for everything.
Uh-uh. Thank aunt Adele.
The internal scans
were negative.
There was no evidence
of auditory anomalies
anywhere on the ship.
As far as the sensors
are concerned
nothing unusual happened
last night.
Ten other people
reported hearing voices
at the same time I did.
WORF:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
We are getting unusual readings
20,000 kilometers
off the starboard bow.
PICARD: On our way.
Report.
RO:
Sensors didn't detect
the phenomenon
until we were almost
on top of it, sir.
WORF:
There's a highly
localized distortion
of the space-time
continuum.
On screen.
Back us off, Ensign.
Nice and slow.
Aye, sir.
Captain, maneuvering thrusters
are not responding.
The distortion field
is fluctuating.
All main systems
just went down.
Power levels
are dropping rapidly.
RIKER:
Red alert.
DATA:
There is an energy buildup
in the distortion field.
We have to get
out of here now.
DATA:
Captain, something
is emerging.
RIKER:
Shields up.
Evasive maneuvers.
Shields inoperative.
The helm is
not responding.
The vessel is on
a collision course.
Impact in
36 seconds.
Hail them.
No response.
Suggestions?
Decompress
main shuttle bay.
The explosive reaction
may blow us out of the way.
Captain, I suggest we use
the tractor beam
to alter
the other ship's trajectory.
Make it so, Mr. Worf.
Engaging tractor beam.
Damage report!
Casualty reports coming in
from all over the ship!
Starboard nacelle has sustained
a direct impact.
We are venting
drive plasma.
Initiating
emergency core shutdown.
Inertial dampers failing.
We're losing
attitude control.
This is the bridge.
All hands
to emergency escape pods!
The core shutdown
was unsuccessful.
We are losing
antimatter containment.
We've got to
eject the core!
Ejector systems are off-line.
Core breach is imminent.
All hands, abandon ship!
Repeat,
all hands, abandon...
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45652.1.
The Enterprise has entered
an area of space
known as the Typhon Expanse.
We are the first
Starfleet vessel
to chart
this unexplored region.
Sometimes I wonder
if he's stacking the deck.
I assure you,
Commander,
the cards are
sufficiently randomized.
I hope...
so.
Something wrong, Mr. Worf?
I am experiencing
nib'poh--
the feeling I have
done this before.
Yes, last Tuesday night.
That's not
what I mean.
I've been having
the same feeling.
Keep dealing, Data.
Eight.
Ace.
A queen. You're going
to give me a queen.
And you're
going to get a four.
Deal, Data.
But no one has bet.
Forget the bet.
Just deal.
Ten.
Seven.
Queen.
Nine.
Jack.
Four.
Deuce.
Six.
This is highly improbable.
How did we know?
BEVERLY:
Wait.
Crusher to sick bay.
Sick bay here.
Is Commander La Forge there?
No, Doctor, he's not.
Wait a minute.
He just came in.
You wanted to see me,
Doctor?
Yes.
Captain... have you
been getting the feeling
that you've experienced
certain things before--
a sense of repetition?
Yes, recently.
While I was reading.
Why do you ask?
There have been
similar incidents
reported all
over the ship.
Feelings of deja vu.
I had a premonition
Geordi was going to
come into sick bay.
A few seconds
later, he did
with the symptoms
of an ear infection.
I was going to run
the standard tests
but somehow, I had a feeling
that they would
turn out negative.
So, I ran an
optical diagnostic
which traced
the problem
to Geordi's VISOR.
His dizziness
is being caused
by a phase shift
in his visual receptors.
It's causing him to see
images that aren't there.
They're like
blurry afterimages.
I ran a scan to see
if I could detect
what he was seeing.
I picked up
minuscule distortions
in the surrounding
dekyon field.
Somehow, his VISOR
is translating
those distortions
into visual impulses.
Could be a malfunction
in the ship's
warp-field generator.
I'll check it out.
Run a localized
subspace scan
to look for
anything else.
Aye, sir.
Keep me advised.
( voices murmur indistinctly )
( murmuring stops )
Crusher to Commander La Forge.
La Forge here.
Geordi, I just heard
what sounded like
voices in my room
but no one else is here.
Sensors just picked up
something strange, too.
We're checking it out.
I'm on my way.
( glass shatters )
Looks like you managed
to record 6.2 seconds' worth.
Let's see if we can
filter the signal
and clear it up
a little bit.
Then I wasn't just
hearing things.
The sound itself appears
to have been real.
However, the acoustic energy
does not correspond
to any ship's system
nor to any voice communication
sent at the time you heard it.
Then where did
the sound come from?
Well, you heard the voices
at the same time
our localized subspace scan
picked up
a dekyon field distortion.
The two may be related.
Let's give another listen.
( voices murmuring
indistinctly )
( murmuring stops )
Computer, perform a
narrow bandwidth analysis.
Eliminate all non-vocal
waveform components.
( voices grow louder
and more distinct )
Can we isolate the voices?
Find out what
they're saying?
Computer,
continuous playback please.
( voices replaying )
( voice replay continues )
There are approximately
1,000 voices overlapping.
The voices are those
of the Enterprise crew.
Our voices.
I'm sorry to call
you all here so early
but we couldn't wait
till 0700 hours.
We think we may
have an explanation
for the odd occurrences
around here.
Commander.
This is going to sound
pretty wild.
Somehow, we've entered
what seems to be
a temporal causality loop.
We think we're stuck
in a specific fragment in time
and that we've been repeating
that same fragment
over and over again.
Is this what's
causing our deja vu?
Yes, but it's
more than that.
In deja vu, you
only think you're
repeating events.
We actually are.
Our theory is this:
Every time
the loop begins again
everything resets itself
and starts all over.
We don't remember anything
that happened before
so each time through the loop,
we think it's the first.
You mean we could have come
into this room
sat at this table
and had this conversation
a dozen times already?
A dozen, a hundred.
It's impossible to tell.
We could have been
trapped here
for hours, days...
maybe years.
CRUSHER:
If what we're
saying is true
those voices I heard
might have been echoes
from previous loops.
It's the same with
the phase shift in my VISOR--
afterimages in time.
If you're right about this,
how did it happen?
How did we get there?
DATA:
I have a hypothesis
that may explain that, Captain.
I have analyzed the recording
Dr. Crusher made.
Most of it is quite ordinary.
150 discussions
about ship operations.
252 conversations
of a personal nature.
Five couples engaged
in romantic encounters...
Your point, Mr. Data.
There is evidence
of some sort of disaster
aboard the Enterprise
severe enough that the Captain
ordered all hands
to abandon ship.
I have isolated three segments
of this recording
that are crucial.
WORF ( distorted voice ):
A highly localized distortion
of the space-time continuum.
DATA:
Collision course.
Impact in 36 seconds.
PICARD:
All hands abandon ship!
Repeat, all hands aban...
( recording stops )
LA FORGE:
Worf refers
to a distortion.
If this were a
temporal distortion--
and if we were
close enough to it--
it's possible that a
large enough explosion
might have ruptured
the space-time continuum.
We collided, exploded,
then got caught in this
repeating loop of time.
If you're right,
perhaps we could escape
from the loop
by avoiding the collision.
That's our guess.
Perhaps we should
reverse course.
For all we know,
reversing course
may be what leads us
into the crash.
No.
We can't afford to start
second-guessing ourselves.
We'll stay on this course
until we have reason
to change it.
But let's do everything that we
can to avoid the collision.
LA FORGE:
Captain, we might
not be able
to figure out
how to avoid this accident
until it's too late.
And if the loop begins again,
we'll forget everything
we learned this time around.
What do you suggest?
If we do find a way to avoid
this collision
we should try to send that
information into the next loop.
Is that possible?
We have seen that echoes or
afterimages from previous loops
appear as distortions
in the dekyon field.
We may be able
to send a deliberate echo
into the next loop.
Like a message
in a bottle.
Exactly.
We could enhance
a dekyon emission
to create
a specific pattern
and send ourselves
a message.
Not a long one, probably
only a few characters.
Maybe one word.
How do we know we'll pick up
that word the next time through?
If the dekyon emission
is modulated correctly
it will set up resonances
in my positronic
subprocessors.
I will receive the information
on what you would call
a subconscious level.
LA FORGE:
Now, there's
the catch.
We have no way of knowing
how this information will
be perceived by Data.
It might be like a
posthypnotic suggestion.
Even with all these
uncertainties, we've got to try.
Take whatever steps are
necessary to send a message.
Dismissed.
LA FORGE:
You know, it's possible
we've tried this
a thousand times
and it's
never worked.
Do you have the feeling
that you've done
this before?
No, I don't.
Neither do I.
Maybe that's a good sign.
Let's test
the emitter.
Particle accelerators
at full power.
Dekyon field active.
Particle flux nominal.
We're in business.
All we need now
is a message.
RIKER:
Senior officers,
report to the bridge.
On our way.
( alarm sounding )
RIKER:
We've got to figure out
how we handled this before.
PICARD:
Back us off, Ensign.
Nice and slow.
Aye, sir.
Captain, maneuvering thrusters
are not responding.
The distortion field
is fluctuating.
All main systems
just went down.
Power levels
are dropping rapidly.
There is an energy buildup
in the distortion field.
We have to get
out of here now.
DATA:
Captain, something
is emerging.
RIKER:
Shields up.
Evasive maneuvers.
Shields inoperative.
The helm's not responding.
The vessel is on
a collision course.
Impact in
36 seconds.
Hail them.
No response.
Suggestions?
Decompress main shuttle bay.
The explosive reaction
may blow us out of the way.
Captain, I suggest
we use the tractor beam
to alter the other
ship's trajectory.
Make it so, Mr. Worf.
Engaging tractor beam.
Damage report!
Casualty reports are coming in
from all over the ship!
Starboard nacelle has
sustained a direct impact.
We are venting
drive plasma.
Initiating emergency
core shutdown.
Inertial dampers failing.
We're losing attitude control.
This is the bridge!
All hands
to emergency escape pods!
DATA:
Core shutdown
is unsuccessful.
We are losing
antimatter containment.
We've got to eject the core!
Ejection systems
are off-line.
Core breach is imminent.
PICARD:
All hands,
abandon ship!
Repeat,
all hands aban...
Captain's log,
Stardate 45652.1.
The Enterprise has entered
an area of space
known as the Typhon Expanse.
We are the first
Starfleet vessel
to chart
this unexplored region.
RIKER:
Sometimes I wonder
if he's stacking the deck.
I assure you,
Commander
the cards are sufficiently
randomized.
I hope so.
Something wrong,
Mr. Worf?
I am experiencing
nib'poh--
the feeling
I have done this before.
Yeah. Last Tuesday night.
That is not what I mean.
I've been having
the same feeling.
Wait.
An eight, an ace,
a queen
and a four.
Deal the cards, Data.
Three. All threes.
BEVERLY:
I was positive
I knew what cards
were going to be dealt.
I was also sure.
Finish dealing
the hand.
Look at this.
We've all got
three of a kind.
First we get a three,
and then three of a kind.
Ogawa to Dr. Crusher.
Go ahead.
Commander La Forge needs you
in sick bay.
I'm on my way.
At first, I thought
the catwalk was spinning.
As it turns out, it was me.
I was lucky Ensign Fletcher
was there to grab me.
It's a long way down
to the bottom of the warp core.
BEVERLY:
You have
all the symptoms
of an inner
ear infection.
That would explain
the headaches, dizziness.
But I don't see any
physi... cal...
What?
What is it?
Geordi, have you
ever had these
symptoms before?
Now that you mention it,
I think I have.
Do you recall when?
No... I don't.
I know we've had
this discussion before
and I remember giving you
this examination.
Let's check
the medical logs.
You've been treated
several times
for headaches
related to your VISOR
but there's no mention
of dizziness.
Must be deja vu.
Both of us?
About the same thing?
I'd like to run an
optical diagnostic.
For an ear infection?
I have a hunch.
Now hold still,
this pulse
may be
a little bright.
( groans )
Have you made
any changes
to your VISOR
lately?
No, why?
I'm detecting
a small phase shift
in your visual receptors.
Crusher to Captain Picard.
Yes, Doctor?
Can you come
to sick bay immediately?
It's urgent.
I'm on my way.
His dizziness
is being caused
by a phase shift
in his visual receptors.
It's causing him to see things
that aren't there.
They're like
blurry afterimages.
I ran a scan to see if I could
detect what he was seeing.
I picked up
minuscule distortions
in the surrounding dekyon field.
His VISOR seems
to be translating
those distortions
into visual impulses.
Could be a malfunction in
the ship's warp field generator.
I'll check it out.
While you're at it
run a localized
subspace scan
to look for anything unusual.
Aye, sir.
Keep me advised, Doctor.
LA FORGE:
Lateral sensors on line.
Subspace scanners active.
Data, would you run
a Level-2 diagnostic
on the warp subsystems?
All threes.
That can't be right.
I have encountered
the numeral three
an inordinate number of times
over the last two hours.
( alarm beeping )
We have a dekyon field
fluctuation
on deck nine, section 28.
Crusher to Commander La Forge.
La Forge here.
I just heard what sounded
like voices in my room
but there's no one here.
Sensors just picked up
something strange, too.
We're checking it out.
I'm on my way down.
( glass shattering )
Dr. Crusher,
are you all right?
I'm fine.
DATA:
I have isolated
three segments
of this recording
that are crucial.
WORF:
A highly localized distortion
of the space-time continuum.
DATA:
Collision course.
Impact in 36 seconds.
PICARD:
All hands, abandon ship!
Repeat, all hands, aba...
Worf refers
to a distortion.
If this were
a temporal distortion
and if we were
close enough to it
it's possible that a
large enough explosion
might have ruptured the
space-time continuum.
We collided,
exploded
then got stuck in this
repeating loop of time.
If you're right about this
then perhaps
we can escape from the loop
by avoiding the collision.
That's our guess.
WORF:
Perhaps we should
reverse course.
For all we know,
reversing course
might be what leads
us to the crash.
We can't afford to start
second-guessing ourselves.
We should stay
on this course
until we have reason
to change it.
But in the meantime,
I think we should do
what we can to avoid
a collision.
Captain, we've
been seeing the
number three
all over the ship--
on consoles,
in a poker game.
DATA:
To date, we
have encountered
2,085 conspicuous examples
of the number three.
All of these threes
can't be coming up by accident.
Maybe someone's trying
to tell us something.
We came to
the same conclusion,
so we ran
a ship-wide diagnostic.
The only unusual
thing we found was
a dekyon field
modulation
in Data's positronic
subprocessors.
What could be causing it?
I don't know,
but if I wanted
to send information from
one loop into the next
I might use a method
like a dekyon emission.
You think we sent
ourselves a message?
It would make sense.
Maybe we are trying to
tell ourselves something.
If that were true,
what could three indicate?
Maybe we should run
a Level-3 diagnostic
on all key systems.
LA FORGE:
That's a good idea.
I'll have the computer
run a pattern-matching
algorithm on
the number three.
RO:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
We're getting unusual readings
20,000 kilometers
off the starboard bow.
On our way.
( alarm buzzing )
Report.
Sensors didn't detect
the phenomenon
until we were almost
on top of it, Captain.
WORF:
It is a highly
localized distortion
of the space-time continuum.
On screen.
How do you think we
handled this before?
Back us off, Ensign.
Nice and slow.
Aye, sir.
Captain, maneuvering thrusters
are not responding.
DATA:
The distortion field
is fluctuating.
GEORDI:
All main systems
just went down.
Power levels are
dropping rapidly.
There is an energy buildup
in the distortion field.
We have to get
out of here now.
DATA:
Captain, something
is emerging.
Shields up!
Evasive maneuvers!
Shields inoperative.
The helm's not responding.
DATA:
The vessel is on
a collision course.
Impact in 36 seconds.
Hail them.
No response.
Suggestions?
Decompress
main shuttle bay.
The explosive reaction
may kick us out of the way.
Captain, I suggest
we use the tractor beam
to alter the other
ship's trajectory.
Make it so, Mr. Worf.
WORF:
Engaging tractor beam.
The tractor beam
will not be successful.
I am decompressing
the main shuttle bay.
( loud whooshing )
We are clear
of the distortion.
Data, what happened?
At the last moment,
I speculated
that "three" might
refer to the number
of rank insignia
on Commander
Riker's uniform.
That indicated to me
that his suggestion
might be the correct
course of action.
Data, you must have
picked up a message
we sent from
the last loop
and stacked the deck
in the poker game
without realizing it.
That is possible.
I may also have
inadvertently been responsible
for the unexplained occurrences
of the number three.
Mr. Worf, end red alert.
And try to access
a Federation time base beacon.
Let's see if we can find out
how long we've been
in this causality loop.
Time base confirms
our chronometers are off
by 17.4 days.
Reset them, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
Captain, we are being hailed
by the other vessel.
Computer identifies it
as the USS Bozeman--
a Federation starship...
Soyuz-class.
Soyuz-class?
They haven't been in service
in over 80 years.
Open a channel.
This is Captain Morgan Bateson
of the Federation
Starship Bozeman.
Can we render assistance?
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation starship
Enterprise.
We were just going to
ask you the same thing.
Captain Picard, your vessel
is not familiar to us.
Captain, have you any idea
what has just happened?
Our sensors detected
a temporal distortion.
Then your ship appeared.
We nearly hit you.
The Enterprise
has been caught up
in a temporal causality loop,
and I suspect
that something similar
may have happened to you.
You must be mistaken.
We left Starbase
only three weeks ago.
Captain...
do you know what year this is?
Of course I do.
It's 2278.
Perhaps you should
beam aboard our ship.
There's something
we need to discuss.
♪♪