Captain's Log,
Stardate 45703.9.
We are en route to Earth
where it will be
my pleasant duty to deliver
this year's
commencement address
at Starfleet Academy.
I'm also looking forward
to seeing Wesley Crusher again.
His flight team will perform
a demonstration near Saturn
that will be transmitted
to the graduation ceremonies.
Captain, Starfleet Academy
is requesting an update
on our estimated arrival.
Mr. Data?
We should be arriving
at Earth
in ten hours,
16 minutes, sir.
Please inform the academy,
Mr. Worf.
And send my regards
to Superintendent Brand.
Aye, sir.
TROI:
Do you know
Admiral Brand?
We've met a few times.
She's a formidable woman.
Sounds like
my superintendent.
When I was at the academy,
we had a Vulcan superintendent
who had memorized
the personnel files
of every single cadet.
Knew everything about them.
It was like having your
parents around all the time.
My superintendent
was a Betazoid--
a full telepath.
When he sent for you
to his office
he didn't have
to ask what you'd done.
You got called
to the superintendent's office?
That's a story
I'd like to hear.
( console beeping )
Sir? We are being hailed
again by the academy.
It is Admiral Brand.
On screen.
Sir, she is requesting
a private channel.
In my ready room.
( com beeps )
Admiral Brand,
what can I do for you?
Hello, Captain.
I know you're a close friend
of the Crusher family.
Yes.
I wanted to inform you
personally.
There's been an accident.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
PICARD:
He had second-degree
burns on the chest
and multiple fractures
of his right arm
but he's going to be fine.
Have they completed
the regeneration series?
I'm not certain.
Wesley's allergic
to metorapan treatments.
I think they'll have to use
a bicaridine substitute.
Beverly...
I should send
his complete records
to the academy infirmary.
Of course,
they probably already have them
but you can't be too sure.
Beverly... he's fine.
I know he's fine.
How did it happen?
Apparently,
his squadron was practicing
on the academy flight range
near Saturn.
They were flying
a close formation.
There was a collision.
All five ships
were destroyed.
Four of the cadets were able
to transport out.
One didn't make it.
Do you know who it was?
Yes, his name was Joshua Albert.
Wesley spoke of him.
They were friends.
Wesley was so excited
to make the flight team.
Of course,
I was a little nervous
but I was proud.
I always knew there was a chance
that something
like this might...
Beverly?
Wesley is alive, and he's well.
There was very little to salvage
from the wreckage.
We did recover one of
the ship's data recorders
but it was badly damaged.
We are attempting
to restore the information
but that will take
some time.
Standard procedure calls
for an immediate investigation
by two command-level officers.
Captain Satelk and I
will be taking depositions
from Nova Squadron
at 1500 hours today.
Commander Albert...
I'm sure that everyone
in this room joins me
in expressing
my deepest sympathies to you
on the tragic loss of your son.
There will be a memorial service
for Cadet Albert
this evening
in the west garden.
It has been suggested
that we should cancel
the graduation ceremonies
in the light of what's happened.
Commander Albert and I
have discussed this
and we've agreed
that commencement
should go forward as planned.
The cadets should know
that even after
a tragedy like this
there are still duties
to perform...
and life continues.
Thank you all
for coming.
It's good
to see you again, Captain.
I wish it were
under better circumstances.
This is an unhappy way
to begin commencement.
If you require
any assistance
then the Enterprise
is at your disposal.
I'm sure we'll be able
to conduct the investigation,
but thank you
for your offer.
( knock at door )
Wes.
Oh...
( sighs )
I was so worried
about you.
How are you feeling,
Wesley?
Not bad.
The arm's a little sore.
We were very sorry
to hear about Joshua.
Would you like
to talk about it?
No. I don't think so.
No, thank you.
I know you're just trying
to be helpful, sir
but it seems like
that's all I've talked about
for the last two days.
And I don't want
to go through it again.
I understand. I just
want you to know
that I'm available if you
should change your mind.
Thank you, sir.
( knock at door )
Hi.
Captain, sir.
At ease, Cadet.
This is my squadron leader,
Nicholas Locarno.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
My mother,
Dr. Beverly Crusher.
Hello, Doctor.
Hello.
Captain Picard.
Mr. Locarno.
I came by to see if Wes
had healed up all right.
And how are you
feeling, Nicholas?
Oh, I'm okay.
I just never lost anyone
under my command before.
I'm afraid that
never gets easier.
Captain, mom...
will you excuse
us, please?
Nick and I have some things
we need to talk about.
Of course.
Let me know
if you need anything.
I will.
We'll see you
at the inquiry.
Good to meet you,
Mr. Locarno.
You, too, sir.
The inquiry is scheduled
for 1500 hours.
Are you ready?
I think so.
Look, don't worry
about it, Wes.
Everything
is going to be all right
as long as we stick together.
MAN 1:
Hey, can't you see
that's a flower bed?!
MAN 2:
Sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Oh, come on.
( groans )
( sighs )
Boothby.
Mm-hmm?
Jean-Luc Picard, class of '27.
I know that.
What happened to your hair?
How are you?
I'm pretty damn
cranky, thank you.
I've already replanted this
bed four times this week.
Let me give you
a hand.
You?
I've acquired an interest
over the years.
Well...
don't plant them
too deep.
The stems will...
Will rot.
Captain Picard.
Of the Enterprise, no less.
And giving the
commencement address.
You sound surprised.
Surprised?
Uh-uh.
Nothing you ever did
surprised me, son.
Except that time
you caught that Ligonian
with a reverse body lift
and pinned him
in the first
14 seconds of the match.
Didn't think you
had it in you.
Well, it was
all in the legs.
All that running I did.
( chuckles )
Boothby...
Hmm?
I don't think that I ever...
I don't think
I ever told you...
how much I appreciate...
Mm-mm. There's
nothing to tell.
Yes, there is.
I... I just wanted to...
while I was here...
Look, you know
as well as I do
I would never have
graduated, if you...
You made a mistake.
There isn't
a man among us
who hasn't been young
enough to make one.
Nevertheless...
You did what you had to do.
You did what you
thought was best.
I just made sure that you
listened to yourself.
At the time, I thought
you were a mean-spirited,
vicious old man.
I was.
And by the way
I was about the same
age you are now.
I didn't speak
to you for months.
You needed to get
your bearings.
I knew that.
The important thing is
what you did with
your life afterwards.
It seems you did okay.
That's thanks enough for me.
Did you know the boy
from Nova Squadron
who was killed?
Josh Albert?
Yeah.
Crusher, Hajar,
Sito, Locarno--
I know them all.
( sighs )
You nervous?
No.
Yes.
That's okay.
So am I.
But we're going
to be all right.
We've got some
tough times ahead
but we've always come through
for each other.
Whatever happens,
I want you all to know
that leading this team
has been the high point
of my years
at the academy.
No one could have asked
for a better team.
Or better friends.
Let's go.
LOCARNO:
At this point, we accelerated
and executed a starboard turn
of 27 degrees.
We came out of the turn
on course for Titan.
And you were still
in the lead position?
Yes, sir.
Continue.
As we entered Titan's
gravitational sphere
I gave the signal
to tighten up and move into
a diamond slot
formation.
Remaining in
the diamond formation
we executed a low-apogee
turn around Titan
and began a z-plus
25 degree climb
in preparation
for a Yeager Loop.
Approximately nine seconds later
Cadet Albert's ship collided
with Cadet Hajar's.
We had less
than two seconds
to activate
our emergency transporters
and beam to the EVAC stations
at Mimas.
Everyone made it
except Josh.
Thank you, Mr. Locarno.
BRAND:
Cadet Hajar.
As team navigator
you filed a flight plan
with the academy range officer
before the exercise, correct?
Yes, sir.
Did Nova Squadron
deviate from that
flight plan
after you entered
the Saturn range?
No, sir.
And how do you explain the fact
that the low-apogee turn
around Titan
was at least 2,000 kilometers
closer to the moon
than indicated in your plan?
We were still within
flight safety parameters, sir.
That was not my question, Cadet.
( clears throat )
We had discussed
changing our approach
after I filed the flight plan.
The final decision was made
en route to Saturn.
I didn't consider it
significant enough
to mention here.
I apologize
for the confusion, sir.
I should have been more precise.
( audience murmuring )
Did you see Mr. Albert's
ship break formation
before it collided
with your ship?
No, sir.
My first indications of trouble
were when my proximity alarm
went off.
You may be seated.
Did any of you see the
collision take place?
No, sir.
Cadet Sito...
you were in
the tail position.
Therefore you should have seen
any sign of trouble
from Cadet Albert.
And you saw nothing?
That is correct, sir.
Did your attention falter?
No, sir.
I was flying solely
on sensor readings at the time.
I did not have any visual
contact with Cadet Albert's ship
when he broke formation.
( quietly ):
Sensor readings?
( agitated murmuring )
What's wrong?
Well, it's unusual to
fly on sensors alone
during this type
of maneuver.
A pilot relies on visual
clues from the other ships
to maintain formation.
( rings bell )
( whispering stops )
If you were flying
on sensors alone
perhaps you could tell us
the orientation of his ship
before the collision.
I don't know, sir.
You were flying a ship
traveling 80,000 kph
with Cadet Albert's ship
less than ten meters away
and you don't know
what his orientation was?
I don't remember, sir.
Sir, may I?
BRAND:
Go ahead.
Admiral...
( sighs )
Josh was a good pilot
but lately he'd been
having difficulties.
He'd get nervous
during close flybys
and pull away in
the final seconds.
His formation flying
was a little erratic.
And you didn't report this
to anyone?
No, sir, I didn't.
We'd flown together a long time.
I thought he could handle it
if I gave him a chance.
I was wrong.
BRAND:
Then you are saying
that the accident
was Cadet Albert's fault.
I think Josh got frightened
and tried to pull out
of the turn prematurely
and then crashed
into Cadet Hajar.
Josh was our friend.
We didn't want him
to be remembered
as someone who panicked.
Please be seated.
I am very disturbed
by what I have
heard here today.
By your own admission
you allowed
your teammate to fly
when you knew
he was having difficulties
maintaining formation.
That demonstrates
a serious lack
of judgment.
I am also disturbed
by the fact
that you did not come forward
with this information
immediately.
We should have
the first data
from Mr. Crusher's
flight recorder tonight.
We will reconvene
at 1300 hours tomorrow.
Everything's fine.
Trust me.
LA FORGE:
I don't know, Captain.
The academy has
one of the best
reconstructive analysis
labs in Starfleet.
I'm not sure there's
much we could contribute
to the investigation.
Yes, that may well be...
but Wesley's one of our own.
Understood, sir.
We'll get right on it.
Good. I've spoken
with Admiral Brand,
and she's agreed
to allow us access to all
of the physical evidence
and testimony.
Thank you, gentlemen.
You shouldn't
have said it, Nick.
Josh wasn't responsible
for what happened.
I had to do something.
You said that we weren't
going to have to lie to them.
We all agreed not
to lie to them.
I didn't lie.
Everything I said
was the truth.
The accident was
not Josh's fault.
Look, he was
my friend, too, Wes.
I worked to get him
on this team
but the truth is, he panicked.
We don't know that.
Of course, we do.
None of us has wanted
to say it out loud
but we've all had
the same thought.
Haven't we?
He must have pulled away
too soon.
I think he got scared.
Sito?
Wes, I know you want
to protect his memory--
we all do--
but we have to look out
for ourselves now.
What do you want us to do?
Walk in there and tell them
everything that happened?
We might as well
turn in our uniforms
and start packing our bags.
Are we ready
for that?
We'll take this
one step at a time.
This is the preliminary report
from your flight recorder.
It was damaged so
badly in the crash
that the lab could
only retrieve
a third of the
total telemetry
from the recorder.
And all of it
is before the collision.
There's no problem here.
I don't know
if I can do this, Nick.
SITO:
You don't have to lie.
Just don't volunteer
any new information.
The first night
I met you, Wes
I knew I wanted you
on this squad.
You, more than any of the rest
would understand
what it means
to be able to count on someone
'cause you've
been out there,
putting yourself
on the line.
You know you've got to be
able to count
on the people on your team
because your life
is in their hands
and their lives
are in yours.
We made a promise
to each other,
right in the beginning
that we'd
stick together.
We were Nova Squadron.
Nobody else
could say that.
And even after
we graduated
we'd try to get posted
on the same duty.
We were going to be a team
for a long time.
Josh can't be a part
of those plans anymore
but I think he would still
want us to be a team.
What do you think?
Mr. Crusher.
Sir.
At ease.
Am I interrupting?
No. I was just
going over
my deposition
for tomorrow.
They told me
you'd be here.
I found this
in Josh's room.
I think it belongs to you.
Our ski trip.
Josh and I went
to Calgary last month.
He forgot his sweater,
so he borrowed one of mine.
He told me you helped
him with his classes.
A little.
He only needed help
in statistical mechanics.
If Josh had a weakness,
it was mathematics.
No, he could do it.
He just didn't like to.
His mother and I thought
he'd never get
out of calculus.
Then he found out
what the academy
entrance requirements
were like and...
that turned him around.
He stayed after class
got a tutor.
He really worked hard.
He never gave up
on anything.
And he had a lot
of respect for you
and everybody
on the team.
I realize it
was his fault...
and everybody could
have been killed.
And I want to
say that, uh...
I want to say I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that
he let you down.
BRAND:
Are you ready,
Mr. Crusher?
Yes, sir.
This is the beginning
of our run toward Titan.
I'm on the right wing.
Where is Mr. Albert
at this point?
He was on my port quarter
approximately
50 meters away.
We've just received the signal
to begin
the diamond slot formation.
That's Cadet Locarno
coming into view now.
We're in a
20-degree turn
around Titan.
We should be coming out of
Titan's gravity well about now.
LOCARNO ( over com ):
Okay, people, follow me in.
BRAND:
That is the extent
of the data
we were able to recover
from the flight recorder.
Mr. Crusher,
would you describe
what happened
after you left
orbit of Titan?
Once we cleared the moon
Mr. Locarno led us
into a Yeager Loop.
Approximately
nine seconds later
my proximity
alarm went off.
I tried to veer away, but it
was too late, and I was hit.
I lost control of my ship.
A power coupling
exploded in
my cockpit.
I don't know how
but I managed to activate
my escape transporter.
And the next thing I remember
is finding myself
on the emergency
EVAC station on Mimas
with the rest of the squadron--
except Josh.
Do you have anything
to add to your testimony?
No, sir.
Mr. Crusher, will you describe
a Yeager Loop.
The ships begin
in a diamond slot formation
and climb and loop backwards
at a steep angle
and at the peak of the loop
turn over and accelerate
in a new direction.
Mr. Crusher, did your team
remain in formation
throughout the loop?
Yes, sir.
I want you to be
absolutely clear
on this point, Mr. Crusher.
Before the collision,
was Nova Squadron
in a diamond slot formation?
Yes, sir.
Computer, display
Saturn NAVCON file
6-379.
These images
were obtained
from a navigational
control satellite
in orbit around Saturn
during a standard sensor sweep.
Computer, freeze image.
Magnify sector
Gamma Three
and enhance.
This image
was recorded
when your ships moved briefly
into the satellite's
sensor range.
According to
the time index,
what you see
on the monitor
took place seven seconds
after Nova Squadron completed
the Yeager Loop.
Mr. Crusher,
are these ships
in a diamond slot formation?
No, sir.
What is your explanation,
Mr. Crusher?
I have none, sir.
Everything's going
to be okay, Wesley.
There must be
an explanation
for all of this.
Data and Geordi are
already analyzing
the flight recorder and
the satellite transmission.
Why?
Well, there must be something
wrong with the satellite data.
It might have been
tampered with.
Mom...
Well, there must be
some explanation for this.
I know you're telling the truth
but the satellite data made it
look as if you were lying.
I've spoken with
the other parents.
I am going to talk
to Admiral Brand
and ask her to
delay the inquiry...
Mom.
Don't.
You can't do that.
I'm not going
to let them
ruin your career, Wesley.
You haven't done
anything wrong.
Mom...
don't try to protect me.
Please stay out of this.
Ah...
the weeds
keep popping up
in the pittosporum.
Poor plants don't have
a chance to grow.
You could use
a good herbicide
instead of pulling the weeds
with your bare hands.
Mm-hmm, and you could
explore space
on a holodeck instead
of a starship.
Boothby, tell me some more
about Nova Squadron.
Not going well, is it?
No, it isn't.
You remember the parrises
squares tournament of '24?
The final game against Minsk...
It took me three weeks
to repair the grounds
after the celebration.
We had a lot to celebrate.
Our team
wasn't supposed to win.
We were very proud of them.
Well, the cadets today
are just as proud
of the Nova Squadron.
The celebration they held
after Nova won the Rigel Cup
made '24 look
like a dinner party.
To the other cadets
the members of
that team are gods
and that's a hard image
to live up to.
But Nick Locarno--
he watches out for them.
He keeps them together.
Nick is what makes
that team special.
He's their coach,
surrogate father
and best friend, all in one.
A natural leader.
The members of that team
love him.
If he asks them
to do something, they do it
even if it means
going right over a cliff.
Report.
Nothing conclusive.
We do know that
the collision occurred
about four seconds
after the satellite
images were recorded.
But we still don't know
how the ships got
into the new formation
or why the crash occurred.
We unsuccessfully tried
53 different
computational models
in an effort to simulate
the movements
of the Nova Squadron
just prior to the crash.
There are just too
many variables to take
into consideration--
speed, attitude, course...
Did Wesley's flight
recorder indicate
that there was
anything unusual
about the ship, or the
way it was operating?
Well, the starboard power
flow was fluctuating.
However, it was well
within operational limits.
LA FORGE:
Fluidic pressure in
the landing struts was low,
but I don't know
what difference that would make.
We did find that Wesley opened
his coolant interlock
just before beginning
the maneuver around Titan.
That is a bit unusual.
Normally, the interlock
is closed
unless you're performing a check
on the engine coolant levels.
But there's no evidence
that Wesley was performing
that sort
of a check.
Filling the primary
coolant tanks
requires an open interlock
but that can only be performed
at a maintenance bay.
Is there any other reason
for opening the valve?
Well, it's the first step
in purging the plasma exhaust.
That procedure would be
extremely hazardous
while the ship was in flight.
Yeah, the engine would probably
ignite the plasma.
Ignite the plasma...
That's exactly
what they were trying to do.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain.
Can you tell me
what this maneuver is?
It's a Kolvoord Starburst, sir.
Five ships crossing
within ten meters of each other
and igniting
their plasma trails.
It's one of the most spectacular
and difficult
demonstrations in
precision flying.
And it hasn't been performed at
the academy for over 100 years.
Do you know why?
It was banned by the academy
following
a training accident, sir.
An accident in which all
five cadets lost their lives.
I think that Nicholas Locarno
wanted to end his academy career
in a blaze of glory
and that he convinced
the four of you to learn
the Kolvoord Starburst
for the commencement
demonstration.
If it worked, it would thrill
the assembled guests
and Locarno would graduate
as a living legend.
Only it didn't work.
And Joshua Albert
paid the price.
Am I correct?
Cadet, I asked you
a question.
Am I correct?
I choose not to answer, sir.
You choose not to answer?
But you've already given
an answer to the inquiry.
That answer was a lie.
I said the accident occurred
after the loop.
It did.
What you neglected to mention
was that following the loop
your team attempted a maneuver
that was the direct
cause of the crash.
Oh, you told the
truth, up to a point.
But a lie of omission
is still a lie.
Do you remember the first day
you came aboard this ship?
Your mother brought
you on the bridge.
Yes, sir.
You even sat in my chair.
I was annoyed.
A presumptuous child
playing on my ship?
But I never forgot
how you already knew
every control,
every display.
You behaved as though you
belonged on the bridge.
And then later, when I decided
to make you an acting ensign
I was convinced you could be
an outstanding officer.
And I never questioned
that conviction...
until now.
The first duty of
every Starfleet officer
is to the truth-- whether
it's scientific truth
or historical truth
or personal truth.
It is the guiding
principle on which
Starfleet is based.
Now, if you can't find it
within yourself
to stand up and tell the truth
about what happened
you don't deserve
to wear that uniform.
I'm going to make this simple
for you, Mr. Crusher.
Either you come forward
and tell Admiral Brand
what really took place,
or I will.
( whispers ): Captain...
Dismissed!
( knock on door )
Your message said
it was urgent.
They know, Nick.
They know what we did.
Calm down.
Now, tell me exactly
what happened.
Captain Picard called me
onto the Enterprise.
When I got there, he
told me that he knows.
The Kolvoord Maneuver,
the cover-up, everything.
He said that if I
didn't come forward
and tell the truth
now, he would.
You said he figured it out.
Does he have any evidence?
No, but he knew exactly
how it happened.
Captain Picard
doesn't know anything.
He has a theory.
So, let him tell the inquiry
what he thinks happened.
They'll ask us, "Is it true?"
We'll say, "No, sir."
There's no evidence,
so there's no case.
We'll get off
with a reprimand.
I can't call Captain
Picard a liar.
Wesley...
We have to hang on
just a little bit longer.
Then this will all be over.
It's wrong, Nick.
Wesley...
No.
I'm going to tell them
what happened.
You're going to tell them
what happened?
You...
Alone...
Are going to decide
what happens to me
to Sito, to Jean?
You're going to decide that?
I'm not going to lie
to them again, Nick.
I can't live with it.
You can't lie to them.
You can't live with this.
You have to tell them
what happened.
Who the hell are you?
Nick!
You're going to turn us in!
Now, wait a minute...
No, you wait a minute!
He got to you, didn't he?
Picard told you some big story
about duty and honor.
Well, it must have been
a pretty good speech
to make you turn your back
on your friends.
We're Starfleet cadets.
We have a duty
to the truth.
What about your duty
to your friends?
I got you on this team.
I gave you a chance
when there were upperclassmen
waiting in line.
I said, "He won't let us down.
"He was on the Enterprise.
He knows what it's like to trust
somebody with his life."
Well, I guess I was wrong.
If we all come forward
together and tell
Admiral Brand...
We don't want to come forward.
Sito, Jean and me-- we don't
have a problem with this.
But, if you do, then resign
your appointment to the academy
and walk away.
Don't make us pay
for your guilty conscience.
You'd let me
do that?
You'd let me throw away my
career just to save your neck?
To save the team.
That's more important
than you,
and it's more
important than me.
And if I were
in your place
I'd do it,
without hesitation.
But that's me.
BRAND:
Captain Satelk and I
have gone over
your testimony
and the physical evidence
from the crash.
Your statements
cannot be reconciled
with the data collected
from the NAVCON satellite.
Your unwillingness to offer
any explanation
for this contradiction
is disappointing
and raises suspicion.
We cannot escape
the conclusion
that either the data is faulty
in some way...
or you have lied to us.
However, suspicion
is not proof
and I have no proof
that you have lied
to this inquiry.
Therefore,
if no further evidence
is presented,
I have no choice
but to close this investigation.
For filing
an inaccurate flight plan
and for allowing
Cadet Albert to fly
when you knew
he was having difficulties
I'm ordering
a formal reprimand
placed on each
of your permanent records.
I'm also revoking
your flight privileges.
This inquiry is closed.
( bell rings )
Sir?
I would like to add something
to my testimony.
Proceed, Mr. Crusher.
Yesterday, I testified
that the crash occurred
following a Yeager Loop.
That is not
entirely true.
We performed a loop,
and afterwards
broke formation
and attempted
a Kolvoord Starburst.
( audience murmuring )
We knew it
was prohibited.
We knew it was dangerous
but we wanted to do
something spectacular
for the commencement
demonstration.
We pushed Josh into it,
and he wasn't ready.
We thought we
could do it.
We thought we could do anything.
We were wrong...
and Josh died.
Josh didn't let us down, sir.
It wasn't his fault.
Mr. Locarno...
you are the leader
of Nova Squadron.
Do you have
anything to say?
Mr. Locarno?
No, sir.
Mr. Locarno
has been expelled.
They should have
expelled all of us.
They very nearly did.
Mr. Locarno made
an impassioned plea
for the rest of you.
He said that he'd used
his influence as squadron leader
to convince you to attempt
the Kolvoord Maneuver
and then to cover up the truth.
He asked to take
full responsibility.
He did exactly what
he said he would.
He protected the team.
I feel awful.
I've let down everyone--
my mother,
my friends, you.
You should feel bad.
And you will pay
for what you've done.
Admiral Brand has decided
that in addition
to a formal reprimand
your academic credits
for the past year
will be canceled
and you will not advance
with your class.
I understand.
It's not going to be easy
staying here on campus...
everyone knowing what you did.
You have difficult times ahead.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Captain.
You knew what you had to do.
I just made sure
that you listened to yourself.
Good-bye, Cadet.
Good-bye, Captain.
♪♪