Forward tubes armed
and ready, Captain.
Fire.
A direct hit, sir.
The asteroid has
been shattered.
However, the core
is still intact
and still on
a collision course
with Tessen III.
Is it big enough
to cause a threat?
Yes, sir, it is of
sufficient size
and density to cause
planet-wide damage.
Time to impact?
It will reach the upper
atmosphere in 44 seconds
and impact on the planet
11 seconds later.
Ready torpedoes.
Aye, sir.
Sir, the core is composed
of nitrium and chrondite.
It is unlikely
another photon torpedo
will be of any effect.
Mr. Worf,
prepare a tractor beam.
Aye, sir.
30 seconds to impact.
Captain, I am unable
to get a positive lock
with the tractor beam.
There is magnetic field
interference
emanating from
the core materials.
Activate a deflector dish.
If we project a particle beam,
we may be able to produce
a disruptive nuclear effect
within the core.
Aye, sir.
DATA:
Impact in 17 seconds.
Particle beam activated.
The target has been
destroyed, Captain.
The remaining debris
is of no threat
to the planet, sir.
Well done, everyone.
Ensign, put us back on course
for the Moselina system.
Warp four as soon
as we're clear of
the debris field.
Aye, sir.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
My instructions were clear.
They were not!
Before he was allowed
to play, he was to place
his soiled clothing
in the garment reprocessor.
I was not!
I sense a touch of
hostility here, gentlemen.
You were specifically
told that.
You told me that
yesterday, not today.
If I may suggest...
You know very well
the same rule
applies today that...
Please.
Why not simply draw up
a contract which clearly
defines the duties
of each family member?
You mean he tells me
what he wants and I
have to do it.
No. I mean you both agree
to your responsibilities.
And when you've done the things
that you've agreed to do,
then you've earned
the privilege
to do the things
that you want to do.
When he's cleaned his room,
for instance,
then perhaps he's earned
a visit to the holodeck
to fight his
alien monsters.
You suggest bribery.
I suggest working out
an equitable system
with the rules
clearly spelled out...
for the child
and the parent.
You must make a list of
your responsibilities, too.
What would you like your
father to promise, Alexander?
No yelling.
I do n--!
I do not yell.
Well, then, you should have
no trouble with that part.
Why not go back to your quarters
and talk this thing over?
Decide on which points each
of you wants in the contract.
Very well.
One day you're
going to be glad
your father cared enough
about you to insist on rules.
It may be hard to
imagine right now,
but eventually
most children
come to appreciate
their parents.
Riker to Counselor Troi.
Your mother's
just come aboard.
On the other hand...
LWAXANA:
Deanna, my dear,
it's mother!
Oh, I've got such
deliciously exciting news.
You're going to be
absolutely thrilled.
I'm getting married.
You know, with just
a bit of redecorating
here and there,
this Ten-Forward room
should make a very
nice wedding hall.
I beg your pardon?
Ah, where else,
my little one...
but here amongst
all my good friends
and in the presence
of my adored daughter?
Mother, where did you...?
When did you meet
this man?
Who is he?
I mean, marriage?
When did all this happen?
Oh, my poor,
plodding little Deanna
with her questions,
questions, questions.
Wherever did you inherit
such pedestrian genes?
What matters, my little one,
is that your mother's happy.
Mother, if you're happy,
then I'm happy for you.
I only asked who he is
and where you met him.
Those are not
unusual questions.
He's such a wonderful
man, and he has such
good breeding.
Oh, I tell you,
he's absolute perfection.
Who is he?
He's Campio, third minister
to the conference of judges
from the planet Kostolain.
Royalty, my little one...
BOTH:
Naturally.
I didn't even know you'd
ever been to Kostolain.
Or was he on
some diplomatic mission
to Betazed?
Well, uh... um...
neither, actually.
Uh, you see, we haven't
exactly met yet, really.
Oh, but the profiles
we've exchanged...
why, they were in such
accord that you could
weep, my little one.
You would weep at
the harmony between us.
Mother, don't you think
it would be a good idea
if you actually met the man
you're going to marry
before committing to
spend the rest of
your life with him?
Deanna, I love you but
you do make everything
sound like an epitaph.
ALEXANDER:
I don't want to agree.
But you have to
agree. That is what
an agreement is.
Counselor Troi,
excuse the intrusion,
but we're having
some difficulty
drawing up our contract.
Hmm?
Mrs. Troi.
Hmm.
He's not fair.
The boy is unreasonable.
Well, of course
he's unreasonable.
He's a child.
Aw... and such
a child.
You know, making
little boys reasonable
only gives them pimples.
Alexander,
this is my mother.
Alexander?!
What a wonderful name.
You know, I once knew
a tall, handsome warrior
named Alexander.
Oh, he utterly adored me
and we went everywhere--
simply everywhere.
Have you been
anywhere yet...?
Contract?!
What contract?!
Between father and son.
A fair and balanced way
to achieve a mutual
sense of order.
Well, how ghastly
for you.
And you are doing this to
your own child, Mr. Woof?
Mother!
It is Worf, madam.
Contracts are usually
between people
who don't really trust
one another.
A child who is trusted
becomes worthy
of that trust.
Mother, will you kindly
stay out of this?
And if he does not perform
his contractual duties,
I assume he
will be chastised.
He will be...
sanctioned, yes.
Mm-hmm, and if you fail
to perform your duties,
what is the child
supposed to do about it?
Mother,
will you please...?
I, not perform my duty?
Alexander, now
life's true gift
is the capacity
to enjoy enjoyment.
Now...
Hmm! Have I
arrived too late?
Or, uh... can you
still smile?
( laughs )
( sighs )
Married?
She's getting married?
Yes. If we stay on
our present course,
we should rendezvous with
her intended in 31 hours.
I will not have
that woman continuing
to use this ship
for her convenience
simply because
her daughter
happens to be
one of my officers.
Apparently, Deanna
being on board is only
part of the reason.
The other reason being?
She thinks the honor
of giving away the bride
should fall on you.
Permission for
an onboard wedding
is granted, Number One.
Nothing would please
me more than to give
away Mrs. Troi.
( chuckles )
Ah, my little warrior!
And how are you
this morning?
Oh, I see.
Being punished
for something, are we?
It's just my regular time
to meet with Counselor Troi.
She's not here yet.
Then you're early.
That's very responsible
of you.
No, I just wanted
to be out of my room
be-- before...
Before what?
Now, if we're to
be real friends,
we've got to share
only the truth.
Why?
Well, for one thing,
it's easier.
When you tell the truth,
you never have to remember
later what you lied about.
But mostly, a true
friend is a person
you can always tell
the truth to without
worrying about it.
I... I wanted to leave
before my father
got back.
Oh.
I hate him.
I wish my mother
were here...
but she died.
That's not very
fair, is it?
All he cares about
are rules.
I'm supposed to
do everything right
all the time.
I don't know how.
Oh, to tell you the
truth, little warrior,
neither do I.
But... I do know
one marvelous thing
we can do with rules.
I'm supposed to wait
for Counselor Troi.
Exactly.
I'll bet you've never
been to a colony of
free spirits.
What do they do there?
Oh! Whatever they want.
Artists, philosophers,
freethinkers,
and people who
don't quite fit
other people's rules.
Personally, I come
for the mud baths.
You-- oh, you're going
to adore the mud baths.
Um...
( beeping )
Ah, computer.
I'm assuming that you
have the Parallax Colony
on Shiralea VI?
That program
is available.
Oh, good.
Then, uh,
run it for us, dear.
( gasps and laughs )
( laughs )
What's that?
A wind dancer.
He stands guard.
You see, only those
whose hearts are
joyous may enter.
Aw...
Oh, come on.
Oh!
Fire sculptor.
We'll chat with her later
if you're not wearing
anything flammable.
Hello.
A few of us are just
gathering together
for our laughing hour.
Would you care to
come laugh with us?
Actually, we were about
to experience a mud bath.
Were you?
What an idea. Bink!
My friends and I
will join you.
One can always...
laugh in the bath.
( laughing )
Do you ever drop one?
Oh, no.
No, no,
these are my worlds.
I protect them.
I am a master of worlds,
and they fly only as I wish.
( Lwaxana laughing )
Ooh.
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
Ooh!
We are having guests
for laughing hour.
Would you care
to join us?
We'd love to.
No, thank you.
Yes.
No.
Why do you always say no
when I say yes?
I don't.
You just did.
There you go again.
You're the most
negative person.
Why are they arguing?
They're friends.
They love
contradiction.
They thrive on challenge.
They flourish
in conflict.
Then why
are they friends?
Oh, well, who else
you going to fight with
if not your friends?
Hold!
What is the lesson
for today?
Oh, damned if we know.
We're just here for
some fun in a mud bath.
Every moment
requires a purpose.
No, it doesn't.
Every purpose
requires a plan.
He does this every day,
usually while everyone's
food is getting cold.
( yawning )
It's rather boring.
The higher...
the fewer.
Well, that's a conversation
stopper if I ever heard one.
WOMAN:
And you're being stubborn.
MAN:
I am not. You are.
I am not.
Yes, you are.
Excuse me.
If you're gonna argue,
you should remember...
( in deep voice ):
the higher...
the fewer.
So...
my little warrior
wants to see more
out of life than
just fighting, eh?
Oh, the mind opens,
and in creeps wisdom.
Alexander.
( muttering )
( door chimes )
Come.
Isn't Alexander
supposed to be with you?
He didn't show up
for his appointment.
I assumed he must
still be here.
Computer, what is
the location of
Alexander Rozhenko?
Alexander Rozhenko
is on Holodeck Two.
Is he there alone?
He is with Lwaxana Troi.
To all the creatures
within us.
( laughing )
To all the creatures
within us?
Well, of course.
Every one of us has
a thousand different kinds
of little people
inside of us.
And some of them want
to get out and be wild
and some want to be sad
or happy or inventive
or even just go dancing.
That's why we all have
so many different urges
at different times.
And all those different
little people inside of us?
We must never be
afraid to take them
with us wherever we go.
I mean, who knows when
we may need one of them
to pop up and rescue us
from ourselves?
Ah, variety,
my little Alex.
The great secret is
not the variety of life,
it's the variety of us.
Are we ready
for the entertainment?
Yes. Bring on
the entertainment.
Ah!
( exotic dance music playing )
TROI:
Mother?
( gasps )
LWAXANA:
Little one.
Mr. Woof, come.
Join us.
Mother, I'm trying
to help the boy
learn the value
of responsibility.
You're not helping
by giving him a lot
of mixed messages.
I exposed you to all sorts
of mixed messages when
you were that age.
You still turned
out deadly dull.
What are you
so worried about?
Among other things, his
relationship with his father.
Oh!
No more holodeck, Mother.
Oh...
Please.
Anyway, why aren't
you all absorbed in
your wedding plans?
It's only three days away.
I'm letting Mr. Homn
handle all the
mundane details.
He knows my tastes.
Mother...
Deanna, there is
absolutely
nothing to do,
you nosy little girl.
Campio's already sent me
his mother's wedding gown,
which Mr. Homn is
now altering for me.
Outside of that, there
really isn't anything else...
Wedding gown?
Mother, stop.
You're telling me you're
not going to be naked
at your own wedding?
Campio is from
a different planet
with different traditions.
He would not approve
of a traditional
Betazoid wedding,
so I am happily adapting.
Now, it's as simple as that,
and I need some tea.
I can't believe
I'm hearing this
from the heir to the
Holy Rings of Betazed,
holder of the Sacred
Chalice of Rixx.
Oh! Oh, why can't I ever
work this replicator?
Mother, I think it's
time to talk about
this mysterious marriage
to a man you've never met.
Computer,
some Jestral tea, please.
Oh, anyway, why
shouldn't I get married
if I choose to?
You make everything
into such a mystery.
There is no mystery,
Deanna,
except about
this Petrokian sausage.
The tea-- all I wanted
was a cup of tea.
Oh, dear, I think
your replicator's having
a nervous collapse.
Oh...
A level-4 diagnostic
of the food
replication systems
have failed to detect
any faults in the
orientation terminals.
That may be,
but we've still got
over 200 reports
of malfunctioning
replicators.
( beeping )
There's an energy
fluctuation in one of the
utility access corridors.
Well, we better look
into it, whatever it is,
before the captain
decides to order dinner.
Yeah, Dash 6-4.
Here we are.
Huh. Some kind of
intermittent EM
field pattern.
Give me a hand with
that, will you, Data?
Well, there's no
plasma leakage.
Just a little
negative ion charging.
Oh, bad enough, having
to wear anything at all
to my own wedding,
but this?!
( sighs )
Yeah, perhaps, uh,
if we lower the bodice.
Oh.
Uh...
raise the hemline, then.
What a constant joy
you are.
( door chimes )
Oh-- oh, Mr. Homn...
LWAXANA:
Alexander!
( chuckling ):
Oh, my little warrior.
Come here.
Come on.
Come... oh, give me
a great big hug.
( sighs )
Now, you're not
escaping another
appointment, are you?
No, ma'am.
Oh, I suppose eventually
we all have to live up
to our obligations.
Ah... well, now,
tell me.
What brings you here
to brighten my day?
I wanted to say I'm
sorry if I got you
in any trouble.
Oh! Oh, that's
very sweet, dear,
but I really wasn't
in any trouble...
until I saw this dress.
Oh!
Ugly, isn't it?
What's it for?
I'm getting married.
Why?
You sure my daughter
didn't send you?
Oh, just a joke.
People get married
because, uh...
because they want to spend
their lives with someone.
Their whole life?
Uh-huh.
They must have to like
that person a lot.
Well, if you're
young and lucky,
it will be someone
you like a lot, yes.
( sighs )
And, uh...
and if you're older...
Are you very old?
Uh...
Um...
I'm alone, Alex.
And when you do get older
and can no longer
pick and choose
from whatever
may come your way...
then you, uh, then you do
what we call a compromise.
It keeps you
from being afraid.
We have traced the failure
to a data net interface
which routes replicator
selections to the
correct subprocessors.
When we opened the panel,
we discovered that
the interface
had been transformed
into a gelatinous material
that we haven't
been able to identify.
( alarm buzzes )
We have an
intermittent failure
of the inertial
damping system.
Take us out
of warp, Ensign.
Primary attitude control
has failed.
We're going
to secondary systems.
( alarm beeping )
We have lost
helm control, sir.
Try a manual bypass
of the damping systems.
Aye, sir.
Backup generators?
Coming on-line now.
How long before we
regain attitude control?
We're almost there.
Ensign, put us back
on course, but stay
at impulse for now.
Did something hit us,
Mr. Worf?
Negative, sir.
The inertial dampers
shouldn't fail
without kicking in
the automatic bypass.
I want to know
what went wrong.
Analysis in 30 minutes.
The same thing that
happened to the replicator
happened to the stabilizer.
The transfers
in both systems
were turned into this.
Some sort of corrosion?
We have not yet identified
the substance, Commander.
Whatever it is,
it looks like there's been
a conversion process,
transforming
some of the metal
into gelatinous residue.
But what caused
it is a mystery.
The replicators
and the stabilizers--
two totally
unrelated systems.
Yes, sir, and we
still don't know why
the sensors didn't
pick up the problems.
Let's run a mass
spectrometer analysis
and find out what
this stuff is.
MAN:
Transporter Room One
to Captain Picard.
Minister Campio
is beaming on board, sir.
I'll be right there.
The bridegroom.
Ah, Campio!
My dear!
Your compatibility profile
doesn't do you justice.
I, of course, am
Lwaxana, and any
introductory compliments
you'd care to make
will be happily received.
Indeed, Mrs. Troi.
You are even lovelier
in person.
Oh, now that worked
just fine.
Now, now, we don't wish
to be too familiar
at this early juncture.
Oh.
Forgive this tardiness.
Ship's business.
Minister Campio,
Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
Welcome aboard.
I thank you and greet
you with appreciation
for permitting this wedding
aboard your fine vessel.
Not at all, sir.
Campio, may I
present my daughter?
Deanna Troi, meet...
um, well,
your future stepfather,
come to think of it.
Oh, yes, if I recall
the profile, you are
the ship's counselor?
I am, sir.
And my escort, who
need not be addressed
in this company,
Protocol Master Erko.
Uh, Campio, personally,
I absolutely adore
all the ostentation
I can get, but, uh, hmm...
protocol master?
I would not do you
nor our benevolent hosts
the disservice of
failing to ensure
that priorities
are observed.
Oh, yes, yes.
How very thoughtful.
After all, it would
be unpardonable
simply to abandon
ourselves to the moment,
would it not?
Oh, unpardonable.
Well, it looks like
the only alloy
common to both the
replicator and the
stabilizer is nitrium.
Computer, analyze
the nitrium content
of both the affected
stabilizer and replicator.
There is no nitrium
present
in the affected stabilizer
or replicator.
( sighs )
There is none present
in the residue, either.
According to
the mass spectrometer,
the elements in the residue
have been broken down
into simpler
molecular structures.
That would suggest
the nitrium
has been organically
metabolized.
Maybe that's it, Data.
If a living organism
ingested the nitrium...
This residue would be
the waste left behind.
Well, if that's true--
if something's eating away
at the nitrium on the
ship, then that means
that the dilithium
chamber is vulnerable
as well as the power
transfer conduits.
We'd better get
to engineering.
ALEXANDER:
Ha!
WORF:
Eat, son.
Ha!
What are you doing?
What is that noise?
Ha!
It's my laughing hour.
Ha! Ha!
That is enough, please.
It is your dinner hour.
Eat.
Ha!
I promised to meet
Mrs. Troi for another
lesson in happy wisdom. Ha!
Will you stop doing that,
please?
Ha!
Alexander,
eat your food.
Wisdom will wait,
I assure you.
I promised. Should I
break my promise, Father?
A Klingon never
breaks his word.
Where are you going?
You said no Klingon
ever breaks his word.
I did not mean now.
Now just sit down and eat.
I don't understand, Father.
You're confusing me.
Understand later.
Just eat.
Father...
The higher, the fewer.
I don't wish to be
authoritative, my dear,
but Master Erko says that
now is our proper time
for discussion of
certain details.
Oh, well,
I certainly don't want
to be considered
anti-Erko, dear,
but I did promise Alexander
one more holodeck trip.
Come along,
my little love.
Surely there'll be
other occasions
for you to spend
time with the boy.
Oh, my goodness, Campio.
You and I are going to have
the rest of our lives.
I'll tell you what.
I'll be back here
with you in one hour
exactly, all right?
Minister, the woman
should not be addressing
you in the familiar.
( gasps )
Mother, we have to talk.
Yes, we certainly do,
dear, but not just now.
Well, how, um,
how do I address him?
Mother, we've come
for Alexander.
Please forgive
the intrusion.
Preferably, he should
be called by his
ministerial title.
( laughs )
I'll remember.
Oh, um, Mr. Homn,
uh, you make sure
that everyone is--
is comfortable
until we get back.
And especially the, um,
uh, the minister here.
Now I'll be back--
one hour, darling.
I'll see you then.
WORF:
Mrs. Troi?
Hmm?
It is Alexander's
dinner hour.
Oh! Oh, how
thoughtless of me.
I guess we'll just have
to have a little picnic
before our mud bath.
We have, uh, business
to deal with here.
Leaving is simply
not acceptable.
Oh, well, can't we
just pretend that
it's acceptable?
We'll be back.
You are missing
the point.
Alexander, you will
return to our quarters
and have dinner.
But we were going
to go to the holodeck.
Mother, you're undermining
every effort we're
trying to make here.
Oh, don't be absurd.
You poor dear!
Don't they ever
let you change those
colorless outfits?
It is essential
that we begin
a discussion of the
wedding procedures now.
Oh, Minister, darling,
perhaps you and the jerko here
can come with us.
Ah...
Lwaxana, this exceeds
all boundaries.
Oh, well, a half hour, then.
No longer, I promise.
Oh, uh, Mr. Homn?
Your duties.
Counselor Troi,
have you no influence?
Ha!
Lwaxana,
if you will remain,
I may allow the boy
to stay while...
Definitely not!
WORF:
Definitely not.
My son is to
return to quarters.
Nor may a servant
be present
during a prenuptial
consultation.
Well, sir, I'm afraid
even the bride won't be
present for this one.
The dilithium chamber
shows no anomalous readings.
So far, these transfer
conduits are clean, too.
Hold on.
I'm getting
something here.
There's a severe
energy fluctuation
in this access panel.
What happened?
Well, I was
just juggling,
and I happened to...
catch one in my mouth.
It tasted good,
so I ate it.
Before I knew it
I'd eaten up every
one of my worlds.
It never occurred to me
that once they were gone,
I'd have nothing
left to juggle.
If you ever have
a world, plan ahead.
Don't eat it.
( chuckles )
Well, now!
Almost time to get back.
Are you sad?
Of course not.
I'm about to be a bride.
You know that man
you're going to marry?
Mm-hmm.
He would never come and
take a mud bath, would he?
Oh, he might.
Probably not.
You know, maybe this
would be a good time
to get one of
those little people
that live inside of
you to-- to come out
and tell you what
to do or help you
or something.
Alexander, what are
you talking about?
I'm sorry.
No.
Don't you dare
be sorry.
( sighs )
Wh-- what's wrong?
Uh, come along,
Alexander.
Let's not leave everyone
waiting for us.
Once we saw that
photonic trail moving
through the wall,
we realized we must
be dealing with
a metal parasite
of some kind.
We believe the
parasites came through
the ship's hull
after we destroyed
the asteroid near
Tessen III.
Are they attacking
anything other than
nitrium alloy?
No, sir, not
that we can tell.
But we've got
nitrium everywhere--
the computers,
the life support,
the ventilation,
the engines,
even the
dilithium chamber.
Mr. Data, the asteroid
we destroyed-- that
was rich in nitrium.
Aye, sir.
And that asteroid came
from the Pelloris field.
If the rest of that field
is rich in nitrium,
it would make a
natural feeding ground.
We should think about
going back there.
The parasites could
possibly be lured back
to the asteroids
for a meal that's more
appealing than we are.
Mr. Data, how long
to the field?
At warp nine, five hours,
20 minutes, sir.
Picard to bridge.
Riker here, sir.
Set a course for the
Pelloris asteroid field,
warp nine.
Aye, sir.
Captain, with
our sensors unable
to detect the parasites,
and given the speed
with which they appear to be
moving through the ship...
We may not have
five hours, 20 minutes.
I'm aware of that.
How can we slow them down?
In several cases,
an exanogen gas barrier
has been known to
slow the progress
of metal parasites.
They don't like cold, eh?
Make it so.
LA FORGE:
The problem
is finding them.
As soon as we spot
an energy fluctuation,
they've already
consumed all the nitrium
and would have moved on.
Primary power systems
are going down.
I've rerouted to the
secondary generators.
Inform the bridge.
Mr. Data, with me.
Bridge.
Commander, do you
have any suggestions
as to how we could
encourage the parasites
to leave the ship
once we reach
the Pelloris field?
If we reconfigure
a particle beam
with a high
concentration of nitrium
and project it toward
one of the asteroids...
Then they would
follow the beam
like a trail
of bread crumbs.
Very well.
Turbolift velocity
is beginning to
fluctuate, Captain.
Computer,
halt at next level.
Computer, acknowledge.
We have reached
the bridge, sir.
( alarm wailing )
Report, Number One.
Ventilation and
life support are failing
at random spots
all over the ship.
Captain, we have
dropped to warp 5.7.
Picard to engineering.
La Forge here.
What's happening,
Mr. La Forge?
We're losing speed.
The parasites
must have gotten into
the primary warp
controllers, Captain.
I'm trying to do
a bypass patch
to isolate the
backup controllers,
but it looks like warp six
is about the best
I'm going to be able
to give you.
At that speed,
Mr. La Forge,
there won't be
a ship left to reach
the Pelloris field.
Well, do what you have to.
Working on it, sir.
Captain, we are
losing life support
on Decks 11 and 12.
Mr. Worf, have security
evacuate all personnel
from those decks.
Aye, sir.
Engineering to bridge.
We've got warp 6.5,
but I don't know
how much more coaxing
we can do here.
We need more speed
than that, Commander.
The matter-antimatter
injectors are failing.
I'm rerouting to secondary
injector power now.
Watch the antimatter
containment for
any system failure.
Atmospheric systems
are down 27%.
We're going below
tolerable oxygen limits.
We must evacuate Decks
20 through 24, Captain.
Make it so.
Shut down life support
to those decks.
Direct all evacuees
to Decks nine and ten.
Divert emergency life
support to those decks.
Aye, sir.
Time to asteroid field?
If we maintain
our current speed,
two hours,
23 minutes, sir.
Mr. Data, the rest of us
may lose consciousness.
If we do,
it will be your job
to execute the plan
as discussed.
Aye, sir.
COMPUTER:
Structural integrity
of the dilithium chamber
is at 34%.
Estimated breach
in one minute.
Computer, transfer
power from warp engines
to life support.
Transfer complete.
Activate Bussard
collector.
Activated. Breach of
dilithium chamber
in 40 seconds.
Reconfigure
hydrogen-plasma mixture
to include 30% nitrium.
Mixture complete.
Project emitter beam,
heading 042.021.
COMPUTER:
Structural integrity
of the dilithium chamber
is at 28% and holding.
Mr. Data.
The plan was
successful, sir.
Well done.
Mr. Worf,
coordinate your teams
with Dr. Crusher
and Commander La Forge.
Assess damage and injury.
Aye, sir.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45733.6.
Temporary repairs to
the ship have been completed.
Our attention now turns
to matters of
a more festive nature.
( murmuring voices )
You'd think
she'd at least
get to her own
wedding on time.
( door opens )
Minister!
This is infamous!
Infamous!
We must leave
immediately.
Ah... heavenly.
( chuckles )
Every pore in my body
tingles with contentment.
( chuckles )
Isn't it wonderful
how things worked out,
Alexander?
I wanted to teach
you how to grab
the joys of living,
and you turned around
and, uh... and taught me
to not let go of them.
How very mutual.
TROI:
We still have to learn
how to live
in the real world,
Mother-- all of us.
She's absolutely
right, Alexander,
but only when necessary.
( growling )
You're just supposed
to sit here?