Captain's Log,
Stardate 45761.3.
In an effort to bring an end
to their centuries-long war,
Krios and Valt Minor
have agreed
to a ceremony
of reconciliation
to be held
aboard the Enterprise
at a point midway
between their two systems.
I apologize for the delay
in our arrival,
Ambassador Briam.
We had to stop
at Harod IV
to pick up a group
of stranded miners.
Please, Captain.
We are grateful
that the Federation has
taken as much interest
as it has
in this matter.
Was Commander La Forge
able to provide you
with the special cargo handling
provisions you requested?
Indeed, he was.
However, until we
reach the rendezvous
with the Valtese, may
I ask that the cargo bay
be declared
off-limits to all
but the most
essential personnel?
I trust, Ambassador,
that this cargo
is in no way dangerous.
Oh, no. Nothing
of the sort.
I'm cautious
because it's quite
fragile-- and quite
irreplaceable.
RIKER:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
Captain, we've just picked up
a distress call
from a Ferengi shuttle.
Set a course to intercept.
Aye, sir.
Captain, the timing
of our ceremony
with Alrik is critical.
It cannot be delayed.
We'll be at the rendezvous
on schedule, don't worry.
Excuse me.
The Ferengi report
their containment field
is collapsing.
WORF:
Within visual range, Captain.
On screen.
Their reactor core
is unstable, Captain.
How many onboard?
DATA:
Two, sir.
Bridge to transporter
room three.
Boost your output.
Lock onto
the two Ferengi
onboard the shuttle.
We may need to attempt
a long-range transport.
Standing by.
Energize.
Got them, sir.
Mr. Worf, escort our
Ferengi guests to quarters.
Not too close to mine.
Understood.
Unless you can arrange
your own transport,
you will have to remain
on the Enterprise
until we complete
our mission.
That will not be
a problem.
We are in no hurry.
We look forward
to enjoying
the comforts
of your fine ship.
Hmm... quite
acceptable.
It's not what
we're used to,
you understand,
but it will do.
Perhaps your captain
would care to invite us
to join him for dinner
this evening.
The captain dines alone.
A pity.
That was too easy.
( both cackling )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
We've been working
from your drawings, Ambassador.
I hope we're
in the ballpark.
"Ballpark"?
That's an old
human expression.
Mr. La Forge hopes
that we got close
to achieving
what you want.
Computer, run holodeck
program Krios One.
COMPUTER:
Enter when ready.
Astonishing.
It is the ancient temple
of Akadar.
It is this temple that bonds
Krios and Valt, gentlemen.
Two brothers ruled a vast empire
from this site,
until they were torn apart
by their love
for an extraordinary woman.
This is where
the wars began...
and this is where
they shall end.
There are some details
to be added, of course.
Commander La Forge
will be entirely
at your disposal,
Ambassador.
Just let me know
what you need.
Yes, of course.
I must consult
several of
the historical volumes
I've brought with me,
so perhaps we can
reconvene later.
Excuse me!
Excuse me.
Is it true?
Is a Kriosian ambassador
aboard this vessel?
Yes.
Can I help you?
The ambassador's
very busy.
Ah. Do you schedule
his appointments?
I'm the captain
of this ship.
What is it
you want?
Allow me
to present myself.
Par Lenor, of the Ferengi
Trade Mission.
We are pleased
to hear, Ambassador,
that you have at last
negotiated peace
with the Valtese.
Peace is good
for trade--
unless you happen
to be an arms merchant.
( cackling )
PICARD:
Excuse us.
Arms merchant!
In exchange
for the exclusive rights
to transport
all Kriosian products
to the Valt system--
May I suggest that
you arrange to meet
at another time
after the ceremony.
Perhaps that
would be best.
But, but, but--
Listen...
have you had a chance
to see the dolphins yet?
This is something...
Deck seven.
You really don't
want to miss.
Dolphins?
Yes, but--
Picard to Worf.
Worf here, Captain.
Lieutenant, one
of the Ferengi
has just waylaid
Ambassador Briam.
Will you keep them
under a tight leash?
I don't want them
disrupting the conference.
Aye, sir.
Security
to cargo bay one.
Lieutenant?
One of the Ferengi.
Riker to Captain Picard.
What are you doing?
( yelling )
This is
a misunderstanding.
I was looking
for a barbershop.
Apparently, I made
an incorrect turn, and--
Mr. Worf.
Get him out of here.
Confine them both
to their quarters.
Put a guard
on the door.
What is happening?
Emergence.
I am for you,
Alrik of Valt.
No, Kamala.
This is not Alrik.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
starship Enterprise.
That explains why you don't look
at all like your holographs.
I apologize, Captain.
As an empath,
I could sense your authority.
I assumed you were
Chancellor Alrik.
I'm afraid that I require
an explanation, Ambassador.
As do I,
Ambassador.
Why have I been brought
out of stasis prematurely?
It was
an accident.
This is quite
complicated.
Perhaps you and I--
It is not complicated
at all, Briam.
And the captain has no
tolerance for prevarication.
I'm a gift...
to Alrik of Valt.
You mean you are
using this ship
to transport a sentient
being as property?
Not as property.
As a gift.
And I was
concerned that
you might not
entirely understand.
PICARD:
Your concern was
well-justified, Ambassador.
You're angry.
Why?
There is a provision
in the Federation constitution
that protects an individual's
fundamental rights.
Now, once you came
aboard this ship--
You're coming to
my rescue.
What a kind and
generous purpose.
But, Captain, I do not need
to be rescued.
Kamala is the key to peace
between our two worlds.
Why?
In our history
there is a woman
known as Garuth,
who was loved by the brothers
Krios and Valt
with such passion
that an empire fell.
And the wars began
when Krios kidnapped Garuth
and took her
to our planet.
KAMALA:
Like her, I'm an
empathic metamorph--
the first
female metamorph
born on my world
for over 100 years.
A metamorph?
A mutant.
A biological curiosity,
if you will.
With the ability to sense
what a potential mate wants,
what he needs,
what gives him
the greatest pleasure,
and then to become that
for him.
You mean, you change according
to whatever man you're with.
Until I reach
the final stage of bonding,
when I must imprint
upon myself
the requirements
of one man--
to serve as his perfect
partner in life.
BRIAM:
You see,
male metamorphs
are somewhat common,
but females
are born only once
in seven generations.
So obviously,
they are greatly
sought after as mates.
Which explains the
Ferengis' interest.
This mating with Alrik
was arranged since her birth
by the leaders
of both worlds,
in the hopes
of restoring peace.
And you do this
of your own accord?
It is my sole purpose
in life.
Commander Riker,
escort her to quarters.
There's no need for you
to travel in the cargo bay.
Kamala... remain
in your room.
I will speak
with you shortly.
Why were you
in stasis?
Metamorphs have
a long and complex
sexual maturing
process.
I'm in the finiis'ral,
the third and final stage.
It can be an uncomfortable
transition,
not only for me,
but for the men around me.
In what way?
My body is producing
an unusually elevated level
of what you would call
pheromones.
The effect can be
quite provocative.
Perhaps you sense it.
Uh... unfortunately,
I'm not an empath.
Oh, I think you're
more empathic
than you admit...
at least when
it comes to women.
I think you have me
at a disadvantage.
This is the com panel,
the replicator.
You can lower the lights
on a verbal command.
If you have any questions,
you can just ask the computer.
I'm beginning to sense
the elevated pheromones
you were referring to.
You were curious,
weren't you?
"Curious" isn't exactly
how I'd describe it.
You know what's remarkable
about empathic metamorphs?
You mean there's something
even more remarkable about you?
We learn so quickly
what stimulates a man
that the second time's
even better than the first.
Listen...
this has been
very educational,
but I make it
a policy
never to open
another man's gift.
I know my role
in history, Commander...
but it's going to be
a long voyage.
It certainly is.
We'll try to make you
as comfortable as possible.
Riker to bridge.
If you need me,
I'll be in holodeck four.
How can you simply
deliver her,
like a courier,
into a life of virtual
prostitution?
Beverly! Arranged marriages
have been the basis
of political alliances
in many cultures,
including our own.
I'm surprised at you.
She knows exactly
what she's doing.
She has been conditioned
since the day she was born
to believe it's
perfectly acceptable
to exist only
to please men.
But she was born
to do this!
And bred by those people
to seal a treaty
with a seductive
coup de grace.
All right.
Fine, good!
Let's throw the prime
directive to the winds.
Let's detain her here
against her will.
Let's destroy any chance
of peace between these worlds.
Let's interfere
in their society,
their customs...
That slave trader
who calls himself
an ambassador?
He has her confined
to her quarters.
She is a virtual
prisoner
in there.
I didn't know that.
Well, it is your ship.
Maybe there are a few things
you should find out about.
I'll talk to her
about it.
Good.
Lovely breakfast.
Indeed.
( door chimes )
KAMALA:
Come in.
Captain Picard,
what a delightful surprise.
Come in.
Thank you.
Are you comfortable?
Reasonably,
under the circumstances.
It has been brought
to my attention
that you have been told
to remain in here.
That's true, I'm afraid.
Against
your wishes?
At the request
of the ambassador,
who believes I might be...
disruptive to your crew.
The performance of
my crew is none
of the ambassador's
business.
You care about
my well-being.
Thank you, Captain.
I care about...
I care about what happens
onboard my ship.
Yes, I know.
This ship is very important
to you, isn't it?
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes, it is.
Are all captains' lives
so... solitary?
Or just yours?
Don't.
What?
Don't do this,
this--
This you do with men.
I'm afraid my premature
emergence from stasis
has left me a little...
vulnerable to the desires
I sense from men.
Nevertheless...
this is who I am,
Captain.
You might as well
ask a Vulcan to forgo logic,
or a Klingon
to be nonviolent.
I cannot change,
and I don't want to
until the time has come for me
to bond with my permanent mate.
Why does it bother you?
Frankly, it's difficult
for me-- for many of us--
to easily accept that
a sentient being
can live only
to be what
someone else
wants them to be.
But that's what gives
a metamorph pleasure.
But what about
your wishes?
Your needs?
They are fulfilled
by what I give to others.
But what about when
there are no others?
When you're alone?
I'm... incomplete.
What curious questions,
Captain.
Well, under
the circumstances,
I thought that
it would help if I...
if I learned more
about you.
But you know me
better than you realize.
I am independent,
forceful,
brilliant,
and adventurous.
Exactly as you would
have me be, Captain.
I'll speak to the ambassador
about easing your restrictions.
Thank you, Captain.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45766.1.
We have reached the designated
coordinates for the conference
and await the arrival
of Chancellor Alrik.
( plays echoing tones )
Ugh.
I forbid it.
Forbid it?
It's too dangerous, Captain.
She must remain
in her quarters.
You cannot confine her
against her will,
not onboard this ship,
Ambassador.
She is requesting
some freedom of movement,
and I intend
to give it to her.
She is still in
the finiis'ral,
the height of her
sexual allure, Captain.
Every man on this ship
will be fighting over her.
Not every man.
A chaperone?
I would be pleased
to escort you around the ship.
But I was hoping
we might spend
some more time
together, Captain.
I shall be busy
making arrangements
for the conference.
I'm very
knowledgeable
about Valt.
I could be helpful.
I think that
you should enjoy
the hospitality
of the ship.
Mr. Data here will see
to your every comfort.
If you will
excuse me.
The reason
your empathic powers
do not perceive
anything is because,
as an android,
I have no emotion.
I can understand
why Captain Picard
chose you to be
my chaperone.
( conversation and laughter )
MAN 1:
Oh! Whoa!
MAN 2:
Help me!
MAN 3:
Whoa!
MAN 4:
Oh, gracious!
I'll check in
with you later.
Excuse me,
but I'm absolutely certain
that we met once
at Paloris colony.
I've never been
to Paloris colony.
Neither have I.
Why don't we find out
what else we have in common?
Extremely
rude behavior.
He's just
being playful.
Perhaps you would care
for something to drink?
What are you all
having, boys?
Aldorian ale's our drink.
Then it's mine, too.
Yeah!
Bartender?
I believe they're
having a minor
problem with
the replicator.
Uh, they could use
a hand, Commander.
Excuse me.
I believe
I will stay.
Mr. Data's
protecting me tonight.
Oh, protecting you?
From what?
From you, I guess.
( laughing )
I told the captain
not to worry.
I just want
to have a good time
like anybody else.
( men grunting )
Come on down to deck seven.
We'll show you a good time.
Get rid of the android,
and we'll have some fun.
Is there a problem here?
No, sir.
No, no problem.
Tell him,
lady.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
The crowd seemed a bit
too ebullient
for comfort.
Perhaps you would
enjoy a nice
quiet visit
to the arboretum.
( seductive growling )
( subtle growl )
Perhaps the ambassador
is right.
Perhaps I should remain
in my quarters.
I have confidence
in the self-control
of my crew, Kamala,
but there are guests
and civilians onboard.
I understand.
I will volunteer
to stay in my quarters
under one condition--
that you will visit me.
There it is again.
What?
The wall you put
between us.
Kamala, you are
one day away
from an
arranged mating.
Why would you
want me
to visit you
in your quarters?
I said a visit.
I didn't ask you
to make love to me.
A Ventanan thimble.
Early Lapeongical
period, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Have you seen
the Ventanan woven art
recovered from
the fourth colony dig?
Woven art?
Recovered intact?
They say the colors
are remarkably
vibrant
for their age.
I've read about them
for years,
but they were
so delicate
no one expected
to find any preserved.
How do you know
about them?
I stay informed on
a wide variety of subjects.
After all,
one never knows
when the conversation might turn
to Ventanan archeology.
Or to the "dark woman of raven
brows and mournful eyes"
in Shakespeare's sonnets.
Or to the gardens
of Les Eyries,
near the village
where you grew up.
Your empathic powers
told you all this about me?
Not quite that much.
Mr. Data helped
a little.
I see.
My empathic powers
can only sense
a man of deep passion
and conviction...
so controlled,
so disciplined.
I'm simply curious
to know what lies beneath.
Nothing.
Nothing lies beneath.
I'm... I'm really
quite dull.
I fall asleep
each night
with an old book
in my hands.
When a metamorph
finds you interesting,
do not take it lightly.
Oh, I'm not
taking it lightly.
I'm just trying...
to be as dull
as possible.
Will you visit me?
It would be inappropriate.
Is that a yes
or a no?
I'm sorry.
Even the walls
of Jericho fell, Captain.
Why are you doing
this, Kamala?
There can be
only one reason--
because some part
of you wants me to.
( mumbling )
Ambassador.
( clinks coins )
What is the meaning
of this?
Ah. I see you got
our message.
Is this some
sort of bribe?
Oh!
I am not amused.
No, Ambassador.
Well, your attitude
is quite understandable.
This is just
a sample.
The bribe is 10,000 more.
Ludugial gold--
the purest
in the galaxy.
We know the lifestyle
of the Kriosian ambassador
is far from comfortable.
You deserve
to live a life
of luxury.
How dare you
suggest...
The money!
What--
You drive
a hard bargain!
20,000-- but not
an ingot more.
We must have
the metamorph.
She is the answer
to a Ferengi prayer.
And we have
a ship waiting
to rendezvous with
us in three hours.
We can all transport
off together.
Yes!
Thank you for sharing
that information.
I shall pass it on
to Captain Picard.
You can't do that!
Wait! Listen!
BRIAM: What are you doing?
Wait, let's discuss!
Let go of me!
Unh!
( groaning )
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
The Ferengi
have been dispatched
via shuttle
to Starbase 117.
What charges
will be brought against them
depends on whether or not
Ambassador Briam recovers.
We've been able
to stabilize his condition.
If we're lucky, he'll regain
consciousness in a few days.
Set up a level one
craniosacral display.
MAN: Yes, Doctor.
Right away.
I'll inform
the Valtese delegation
that the conference
will have to be postponed.
That won't be possible.
My ability to imprint
on a mate
will only last
a matter of hours
after the completion
of the finiis'ral.
If I hadn't been removed
from stasis prematurely,
a delay might
have been possible.
But now, I will
have to bond
with Alrik
within two days.
But there are points
in the negotiation
that Briam still
has to address.
You are familiar
with the issues.
Familiar, yes,
but...
I can't represent
your people's interests.
You can represent
the interests of peace.
My people will agree.
I'm certain of it.
But there are
customs and rituals
of which I have
no experience at all.
I told you, I'm extremely
knowledgeable about Valt.
I will help you prepare.
( playing echoing notes )
Ah.
Torze-qua.
That's right.
( sighs )
I'm reminded of piano lessons
when I was a child...
( sighs )
preparing for some...
dreaded recital.
Do you still play?
No.
I regret
that I gave it up.
It used to please
my mother.
But I...
didn't like performing
in front of
an audience.
Shy?
No.
Just not very good.
Thank you.
For letting down
your guard,
if only
for a moment.
You will have to...
help me in the pronunciation
of this scroll.
What is it
about me you fear?
Kamala...
Do you find me
unattractive?
I find you unavailable.
I am being
terribly selfish.
I apologize.
We have something
in common, Captain.
When I was a child,
I took music lessons, too.
Really?
What instrument?
All of them.
The entire orchestra?
Plus a few
Valtese horns
that sound like braying
Targhee moonbeasts.
They are said to soothe
the nerves of Valtese men.
My mother never even
heard me play.
I was taken from her
when I was four
and sequestered in
a royal village where I was
prepared to fulfill
my destiny.
Sounds as if it were
a very lonely time for you.
On the contrary.
I had servants and tutors
at my side constantly.
You once asked me
what I'm like when I'm alone.
I've never been.
There was always
somebody there
to educate me
in literature
history, art, sex.
But I've been alone
on this journey,
and I've found
myself thinking about
all the curious questions
you asked.
You wanted
to know who I am.
And as I continue
to ask myself,
the only answer
that comes to me is,
"I am for you,
Alrik of Valt,"
because that's
the truth.
In a day, I will bond
with a man I've never met,
and I will turn myself
into what he wants me to be,
for the rest of my life.
I also once
asked you...
if you were doing this
of your own accord.
I'm honored to be chosen
to serve my people
as an emissary of peace.
But I find it ironic
on the eve
of the ceremony...
which I've spent my entire
life preparing for...
that I should meet
a man like you.
Riker to Picard.
Go ahead,
Number One.
The Valtese ship
has arrived.
Chancellor Alrik
is ready to beam aboard.
( door opens )
Captain Picard.
Chancellor Alrik.
Welcome onboard
the Enterprise.
Your first officer has
described the details
of the incident
with the Ferengis.
How is
the ambassador?
He has not regained
consciousness.
A tragedy.
Your willingness
to assist
is appreciated
by both our peoples.
Well, I'm doing my best,
although I'm finding
some of the rituals
rather demanding.
Rituals...
I am more concerned
about the remaining
provisions of the treaty.
The proposed
trade agreements
are not acceptable.
We still must review
the uncommitted
territories, as well
as discuss
the schedule
for exchange
of technology.
The Kriosians
have authorized me
to make several compromises
favorable to your position.
Good.
Tomorrow, then.
Briam has supervised
the reproduction
of the ancient temple
of Akadar on our holodeck.
Such a sentimental
people, these Kriosians.
It's hard to believe
we have
a common ancestry.
Please.
I suppose they've sent
the metamorph?
Kamala?
Yes.
She is looking forward
to meeting you.
I'm sure
she'll be satisfactory.
Between you and me,
Captain,
I am far more interested
in the trade agreements.
So, tell me quickly.
What is he like?
First impressions?
He's a thoughtful man,
informed.
Did he ask about me?
Yes.
What did you
tell him?
That you were looking
forward to meeting him.
When am I
to be presented?
It'll be the first
order of business,
tomorrow at 10:00.
Would you like
some tea?
Thank you, but...
I should prepare
for the ceremony.
Let me help you
with pronunciations.
Oh, I think I can muddle
my way through.
Please don't leave.
Talk to me.
I love the sound
of your voice.
I'll turn out the lights
and just listen.
I don't want
to be alone.
The lights stay on.
Earl Grey tea.
Hot.
Did you learn that
from Commander Data, as well?
I shall have to have
a talk with him.
Now that I know that you're
listening to my voice,
I find that I... can't
think of anything to say.
A starship captain
must encounter
all sorts
of life-forms.
Am I one of the most unique
you've ever met?
Please say yes.
Yes.
What a nice thing
to say.
Kamala, have I not done
everything possible
to discourage this?
Maybe that's the perfect way
to attract a metamorph.
I don't want to use you
as other men do.
But you're not
other men.
You could never
use me.
That's the very reason
why I'm with you tonight.
I should go.
And you have
an appointment
tomorrow morning,
early.
Light years away.
Quiet this morning.
I'm sorry.
Penny.
What?
For your thoughts.
Penny for your thoughts.
Do you have one?
I'm sure the replicator
will have one on file.
Beverly, may I take off
the uniform for a moment?
Captain?
I need to talk
to a friend.
Of course.
Actually,
it's all your fault.
Mine?
You insisted that I look
into her situation.
The metamorph?
The metamorph.
Kamala.
I spent quite a lot
of time
with her
in the past few days.
And you're right about
several things, Beverly.
Her entire existence
has been orchestrated
for this moment.
And she intends
to go through with it...
to help her people
end the war.
And you're saying there's
nothing you can do about it?
It isn't that simple.
I barely know
who she is, and...
and who she is
changes
the moment the next man
comes into the room.
And I find myself
hoping
that the next man
won't come in.
But, of course,
he does, and...
in a few hours
the ceremony will begin,
and she will...
she will mate
with a man
who cares more
about trade agreements
than he cares
about her.
And I can't help
thinking
how she will
be with him--
how she will change
to accommodate him.
I wish I knew how
I could help.
Perhaps I just needed
a shoulder.
Well, it's there
for you, Jean-Luc.
It always has been.
( door chimes )
KAMALA:
Come in.
Is it time?
Soon.
Do you have
any questions
about
the ceremony?
Many.
I will never
truly love him.
You've not even
met him.
It no longer matters.
I wish I could
convey to you
what it's like
to be a metamorph.
To feel the inner
strength of someone.
To realize that being
with him is opening
your mind and heart to
endless new possibilities.
To hear yourself say,
"I like myself when
I'm with him."
Kamala...
For a metamorph, there
is no greater pleasure,
and no greater wish,
than to bond with
that kind of mate
at the end
of the
finiis'ral...
as I've bonded
with you.
With me?
Who I am today,
I will be forever.
Data to Captain Picard.
Not now, Data.
But, sir,
Chancellor Alrik
is waiting to receive you
in holodeck seven.
Acknowledged.
You can't go through
with the ceremony.
Would you
ask me to stay
and ask two armies
to keep fighting?
Having bonded
with you,
I've learned
the meaning of duty.
He'll never know.
I'm still empathic.
I will be able
to please him.
I only hope
he likes Shakespeare.
KAMALA:
I am for you,
Alrik of Valt.
Your service to
both our peoples
is greatly
appreciated, Captain.
Your preparations
made
the negotiations
simple, Ambassador,
and...
Kamala was able
to guide me through
the rituals.
I must admit,
I am curious.
Curious?
I was chosen
for this mission
for a very simple reason--
I'm 200 years old.
The temptations of
a beautiful metamorph
do not easily reach me.
And yet, I would be lying
if I were to claim
that even at
my age, they--
they do not
reach me at all.
But you?
You worked with her,
side-by-side
for days.
How could you
resist her?
Ambassador,
have a safe trip home.
Energize.