I like to cook
all kinds of stuff--
like yogurt and raisin salad,
chocolate chip pancakes,
and purple omelets.
Purple omelets?
You put grape juice
in the eggs.
Isabella doesn't
like it very much.
She says it tastes funny.
I can see her point.
Would you like some sugar
with your tea?
Yes, please.
Isabella,
would you like some?
Yes, but she takes
two cubes.
Mm-hmm.
I'll bet Isabella
is very pretty.
She's very, very pretty.
She has blonde hair
and a blue dress
with white buttons.
Her ears are pierced
and she's tall.
Maybe you could draw me
a picture.
I'd love to see
what she looks like.
You don't think
she's real.
I think she's real for you,
and that is real enough
for me.
Honey, I think it's time
for you to go now.
You don't wanna
keep Keiko waiting.
I have to go plant
the nasturtiums now.
I'm Keiko's helper in
the arboretum today.
Is that so?
You go ahead, sweetie, and
be home in time for dinner.
I hope
I see you soon.
Maybe we can be friends.
Okay.
Counselor Troi?
Yes?
Isabella says
she likes you.
Why, thank you, Isabella.
I can understand your
concern, Ensign Sutter,
but really, you have
nothing to worry about.
It's a normal, healthy
activity for children
to engage in imaginary play.
I'm-- I'm just afraid she's
not making any real friends.
She spends all of her time
with Isabella.
You've been moving
from starship to starship
since Clara was two years old.
Maybe Isabella provides
a constant companion.
She knows this is one friend
she won't have to leave behind.
You're probably right.
Give Clara a chance.
Once she learns to make
new friends on the Enterprise,
you'll probably find
that she'll leave
her imaginary world behind.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45852.1.
The Enterprise has arrived
at FGC-47--
a nebula which has formed
around a neutron star.
We are eager to investigate
this unique formation.
We've got elevated
quantities of hydrogen,
helium and trionium,
but nothing
the shields
can't handle.
Shields up.
Take us in, Ensign.
One-quarter impulse.
Aye, sir.
In order for the
lateral sensors
to complete their
scheduled observations,
additional processing time
will be required.
We could steal
a couple of hours
from the engineering team
while they're recalibrating
the thermal
interferometry scanner.
Will two hours
be enough time
to complete the
high-resolution series
on the neutron star?
No problem.
We'll just double up
the main sensor bandwidth
while they're freeing up
the lateral units.
Hmm.
And then after dinner,
then what?
We went to the holodeck
and took a walk on
the Champs Elysees.
The neural scanner still
seems to be a bit off.
Let's check the
sensor calibrations.
I'll run a diagnostic.
And...?
And?
After Paris?
He has shore leave
next month.
He asked me to go
to Risa with him.
No problem, Nurse McClukidge
can cover for you.
I don't think
I'm going, Doctor.
I hear it's a very
uninhibited atmosphere.
Personally, I don't
think I'm ready
for that kind of "fun."
Try to talk him
into Tavela Minor.
They have a cruise
down the Jokri River.
The iridescent currents
are beautiful.
( giggles )
See, Isabella?
You have to stick your finger
into the soil
as far as it can go.
We're making a hole
for the seeds.
Now, they need to be watered.
But the baby seeds
are very small,
so we mustn't give
them too much to drink.
( Clara humming
Old MacDonald Had A Farm)
( continues humming )
( another girl humming along )
Hello?
Is anybody there?
GIRL:
Hello.
Isabella?
Hello, Clara.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Isabella,
how come I can see you?
Is something wrong
with the way I look?
No. It's just
I've never seen you before.
Not for real.
Well, now, you can
see me for real.
Doesn't that make you happy?
Yes. It's wonderful.
Can we go now?
We better finish planting
the seeds first.
I'm tired of planting.
Let's do something else.
Like what?
Like... I would really
like to explore the ship.
We better finish
planting first.
I promised Keiko.
We can finish later.
Let's go look around.
I better ask my daddy.
Your daddy won't mind.
We can tell him later.
Come on.
So, what are we gonna
call this nebula?
"FGC-47" just doesn't
have the proper ring to it.
Why don't we call it
"Sutter's Cloud"?
( chuckles )
The rotational period
of the neutron star
is 1.35 seconds.
That's a bit on the long side.
Sutter, see if you can get
a reading on
the particle flux.
Aye, sir.
No, I was thinking
about something
more along the lines
of the "La Forge Nebula."
It's got sort of a majestic
sound, don't you think?
Given the selections,
I prefer FGC-47.
What was that?
It felt like we
hit something.
Shields have
registered an impact.
However, sensors show
nothing in the vicinity.
Forward velocity is down
by .2% and dropping.
Engineering,
report.
There could be something wrong
with the shields, Captain.
We're checking it out now.
Systems are normal, sir.
So, did we hit
something or not?
Shields say yes.
Sensors say no.
This is very strange.
Ensign, give me a breakdown
on the shield energy conversion
and then run a spectral--
whoa!
Where did you come from?
I'm Clara Sutter.
That's my daddy.
( sighs )
Clara, you can't
be here right now.
But Isabella wanted
to see Engineering.
I-- I don't care what
Isabella wanted to see.
You go back to our
quarters right now.
But, Daddy--
PICARD:
Bridge to La Forge.
Our speed is still dropping.
LA FORGE:
I hear you, Captain.
I'm increasing the power
to the impulse engines
but forward velocity just isn't
consistent with engine output.
PICARD:
Explanation.
It seems like there's
something increasing
the drag coefficient
on the ship,
but we can't find the source.
If we can't correct it,
we may have to reverse course
and leave the nebula.
Give me a couple of minutes
here, Captain.
Clara, now.
I'm sorry, Commander.
Why do you keep
disappearing like that?
The grown-ups don't
believe I'm real.
When they're around,
I have to be invisible.
Wait here.
The drag coefficient
continues to increase.
Our velocity has fallen by 12%.
( console beeping )
Velocity is increasing.
The ship's speed has stabilized
at one-quarter impulse.
That's great, Data.
What did you do?
I did nothing.
The problem seems
to have corrected itself.
Where did you go?
There was something
I had to do.
I don't have an
explanation, Captain.
We seemed to hit something,
then we started losing speed.
But, so far as we can tell,
there's nothing
out there to hit.
Could some sort
of damping field
have caused us to
lose velocity?
No. We have simulated
several such fields,
but were unable to reproduce
the same drag coefficient.
And we still don't
know why the problem
suddenly corrected itself.
Seems we're looking
at a unique phenomenon.
One that hasn't been
recorded before.
The question is-- do we stay
here and check it out?
Might be dangerous.
DATA: Since we have
only experienced
the phenomenon once,
it is impossible
to estimate the risks.
Captain, I'd like to stay
here for a little bit,
collect some samples
of the gaseous matter,
see what it tells us.
Agreed. Collect your
samples, Mr. La Forge.
We'll proceed
with caution.
Dismissed.
What's in here?
That's the door
to the cargo bay.
We can't go in there.
Let's go someplace
with a lot of people.
Okay.
Isabella, why are you
so serious lately?
What do you mean?
You haven't even
smiled once today.
You're my best friend,
Isabella.
Why?
I don't know.
Because we do things together
and we trade secrets.
Does everybody have
a best friend?
If they're lucky.
Before I had you,
I didn't have one.
Why not?
Every time I made
friends with someone,
my daddy's job
would change.
We moved to a new ship.
It takes time to
make a best friend.
How long?
It depends.
With you, not very long.
You always listened to me,
even when I was sad.
Clara, I'm glad
we're best friends.
Race you.
Okay.
Ready... set... go!
( both laughing )
( gasps )
This area is not designated
for children.
Are you lost?
Where are you
supposed to be?
We were only playing.
We're sorry.
Return to your quarters.
And we will forget
this incident.
Thank you.
Come on.
Hmm.
Okay, I've configured
the magnetic coil
to collect samples of gaseous
matter from the nebula.
Go ahead and activate
the beam emitter.
I'm setting the fractionater
to continuous cycle.
Good. We'll collect samples
from eight random sections.
That ought to give us
a reliable measure.
Commander, I...
I understand
you had a parent
who was in Starfleet.
Mm, two of them,
as a matter of fact.
My father was an exozoologist,
my mother, a command officer.
They must have been posted to
a lot of different assignments.
( chuckles )
Yeah, that's putting
it mildly.
They were always on the move.
Some of the times together,
sometimes separately.
I never knew whether or not
I was gonna be stationed
with my father
while he studied invertebrates
in the Modean system,
or on some outpost
near the neutral
zone with my mom.
Was that hard on you?
I don't remember
it that way.
It must have been
disruptive if you didn't stay
in one place long enough
to make friends.
Well... yeah, I suppose
there were some aspects
of my childhood
that were less than ideal,
but, to me, it was just
one long adventure.
Children are a lot
stronger than you think.
As long as they know
you love them,
they can handle
just about anything
life throws at 'em,
you know?
Thanks, Commander.
Mm-hmm.
No, it's a Samarian
coral fish
with its fin unfolded.
I believe what you are
seeing is the effect
of the fluid
dynamic processes
inherent in the large-scale
motion of rarefied gas.
No, no, first,
it was a fish,
and now, it's a
Mintonian sailing ship.
Where?
Right there.
Don't you see
the two swirls
coming together
to form the mast?
I do not see it.
It is interesting that people
try to find meaningful patterns
in things that are
essentially random.
I have noticed that the
images they perceive
sometimes suggest what
they are thinking about
at that particular moment.
Besides, it is clearly
a bunny rabbit.
Looks as though
someone's lost their way.
Excuse me.
Hello.
Are you looking for someone?
No, I brought Isabella
to see Ten Forward.
Oh, I see.
Well, ordinarily, we only would
let you in with a grown-up.
But since you brought Isabella,
you can be my guest.
Won't you join me?
Thank you.
Now, how about two papalla
juices with extra bubbles?
Just one please.
Isabella isn't thirsty.
Oh.
One juice.
You aren't like
the other grown-ups.
Oh, no?
They don't think
Isabella's real.
Well, most grown-ups
have a hard time
with things
they can't see.
Why?
Well, because they get
preoccupied by other things.
Like what?
Like... how much fuel
it takes to power a ship,
or whether we should go to one
star system or another,
or whether little girls
should go to bed at 7:00,
or be allowed to
stay up till 8:00.
So, their heads get so full
that they forget
about the things that
are important to you and me,
like imaginary friends.
If the other grown-ups
don't understand,
how come you do?
Well, maybe because
when I was your age,
I had one.
You did?
Mmm.
What was she like?
It... wasn't a she.
What was he like?
Wasn't a he.
It?
It was a Tarkassian razorbeast.
It had dark brown fur
and gold eyes
and huge spiny wings,
and it would fly past so fast,
nobody could see it but me.
Sounds scary.
Oh, it was...
especially
when he smiled.
But the best thing about him
was I could curl up
on his furry belly,
and he had the softest
purr you ever heard.
Put me right to
sleep every night.
I tell you, that razorbeast
was a good friend.
So is Isabella.
( door opens )
Hello, Clara.
Hello.
Clara and Isabella and I
were just having
a conversation.
Would you and Isabella
like to come for a walk with me?
I guess so.
Bye.
Bye, Clara.
Bye, Isabella.
Clara, you haven't been
on the ship very long,
so maybe you don't know.
But Ten Forward is
usually for grown-ups.
I know that.
I didn't wanna go,
but Isabella wanted to see it.
If Isabella is making you
do things you know are wrong,
then you must tell her
it's not acceptable.
I try to,
but she doesn't listen.
Deck 32.
Clara, do you want me
to talk to Isabella?
Isabella, it's not
very nice to get Clara
to do things that she
isn't supposed to.
She's over there.
From now on, I want
you to ask a grown-up
before you go to any place
that's off-limits.
What does she say?
She said...
Clara, please tell me
what Isabella said.
She said...
you better
leave us alone.
I'm a little concerned at
the turn this is taking.
It seems Clara is beginning
to do inappropriate things
and blaming them
on Isabella.
She came into
Engineering today.
She said it was
Isabella's idea.
I don't think it's
too serious yet,
but we should make
more of an effort
to get her involved with
real friends her own age.
The children's center's having
a ceramics class this afternoon.
Why don't I take Clara?
I think
she'd like that.
I'll see if there's any room
left in the class.
In the meantime,
I think you should
make yourself more
available to Clara.
Let her know she doesn't
have to rely on Isabella
when she needs
someone to talk to.
Counselor, thank you.
Are you mad at me?
I'm sorry I got
you into trouble.
That's okay.
Are we still
best friends?
Here, you can help me put
this together, if you want.
Clara, why are
grown-ups so mean?
They're not mean.
They're just more
serious than we are.
Sometimes I wish they
would just go away.
You do?
Yes. I don't like them.
I'm bored.
Let's go back
to Engineering.
We're not allowed
to go there.
I thought we were best friends.
We are.
Then why won't
you play with me?
I told you.
You always listen
to the grown-ups.
You don't care about me.
That's not true.
I thought we'd have
fun together
once you could
really see me.
I thought you'd like me.
Let's go to
Engineering, Clara.
Just for a little while.
No one will know.
It'll be our secret.
And if they find us,
we'll tell them we got lost.
( door chiming )
Who is it?
Counselor Troi.
Hello, Clara.
Hi.
I came to ask if you'd like
to go to a ceramics class.
Can Isabella come, too?
No. Let's do something
with Isabella another day.
Well... okay.
Sir, as we move deeper
into the nebula,
sensors indicate that the
levels of helium and trionium
are continuing to rise.
Is it something that the
shields can't handle?
No, sir, we are well
within tolerance levels.
Mr. Data?
Shields have
registered an impact.
But the sensors showed
nothing out there, right?
There is no indication of
anything near the ship.
Forward velocity
is dropping, Captain.
Down by .4%.
Can we go to warp speed?
Until we determine the cause
of the drag coefficient,
I would not
recommend it, sir.
Forward velocity down by 1.1%.
Ensign, increase power
to the impulse engines.
Aye, sir.
Impulse engines
now at full power.
We are no longer losing speed.
Forward velocity is
holding steady.
The drag coefficient
is still present,
but it has stabilized.
Bridge to Commander Riker.
Check with Mr. La Forge,
see if he found anything
in the matter sample
from the nebula.
RIKER:
On my way, sir.
Any luck?
Yeah, take a look at this.
We tried radiating
the subject matter
with just about everything
we could think of.
We didn't find anything
until we subjected it
to a high-frequency
warp field.
We think this is what
we've been running into.
RIKER:
Do you know what it is?
We think so, now that
the sensors can read it.
It seems to be a highly
cohesive form of plasma,
like a strand of energy.
We figure it's a segment
of just part of a network
of much larger strands.
When these things come
in contact with our shields,
it produces a resonant effect,
and that creates
the drag coefficient
we've been experiencing.
Is there anything like this
on record?
No, sir.
Do you know how many of them
there might be?
No, but if we run
the warp field generators
through the deflector grid,
we could radiate a field
outside the ship.
We'd be able to see
for ourselves.
Mm-hmm.
Let's do it.
( children conversing )
Alexander, I thought
you might like a partner.
This is Clara Sutter.
She's new on the
Enterprise.
Clara, meet
Alexander Rozhenko.
I'm making a cup for my father.
Want to help?
Go ahead.
Well, you're supposed
to put 'em in a row...
like this.
Clara, would you like
some clay of your own?
WOMAN:
Here, honey.
I've never made a cup before.
How do you make
the round part?
Well, it's easy.
You take a big piece
of clay like this,
you push your hand into it.
Warp field generators
are standing by.
Captain, we should be able
to illuminate any strands
within 2,000 kilometers
of the ship.
PICARD:
Proceed.
Initiating field generation.
Remarkable.
DATA:
It is an irregular lattice
composed of approximately
47 million strands of energy.
Captain, with this many of them,
the resonant effect
on our shields
could cause a problem.
Agreed.
Ensign, bring us about.
Take us out of the nebula.
That may be difficult, sir.
I am detecting
a significant number
of strands behind us.
Do your best, Ensign.
Aye, sir.
Hot chocolate.
Mmm.
Computer, I need my appointment
schedule for next week.
Kryonian tigers
aren't so scary.
I saw one once.
You did?
My father took me to
the zoo on Brentalia.
All the tiger did
was lick my hand,
and he smelled funny.
( chuckles )
I think we need more water.
I'll get some.
Isabella?
Clara!
I didn't do it.
Who did?
It was Isabella.
I don't see anybody.
She's invisible.
I spent two weeks on that.
That was really mean.
I didn't do it.
I didn't.
Clara...
there's no such thing
as invisible people.
You're lying.
Hey!
Isabella, stop!
Clara?
Why were you being
so mean to me?
Why'd you do that
to my friend?
Because you ran
away from me.
You left me alone.
I had to do everything
by myself.
You're scaring me.
I was going to
protect you, Clara.
I liked you.
But now,
I don't care.
Now, when the others come,
you can die
along with everyone else.
Status, Mr. Data?
At our current speed,
we will clear the nebula
in 12 minutes,
four seconds.
( sighs )
Continue a full sensor sweep.
I want all the information
we can gather.
Captain, forward velocity
is down by .6%.
Velocity down by 2.4%
Mr. Data?
We are moving through
a dense concentration
of energy strands.
Can we go to warp?
Stress on the hull
would be too great.
Captain, the density
appears to be lower
off the starboard bow.
Ensign, bring us to a
bearing 030-mark-5.
Aye, sir.
Forward velocity holding.
Steady as she goes.
Is something wrong
with the cake?
Excuse me?
Well, I see you
sitting here with a piece
of untouched chocolate cake
in front of you.
I assume something's
wrong with the cake,
or something's
bothering you.
I'm sure the cake's fine.
I've just been thinking.
Let me guess.
About the little girl
with the imaginary friend?
I'm wondering if I'm doing
the right thing.
How so?
Well, I know
the best thing to do
is to gradually wean her
away from her fantasy.
And she did make
some new friends today
and had a good time.
But?
But I can't help feeling
that I'm taking something
from her--
something precious--
a part of her childhood
she'll never have again.
Hmm.
Well... I'm not
sure about that.
I was, uh, just telling Clara
about my imaginary friend.
You have an
imaginary friend?
Mmm.
A Tarkassian
razorbeast.
It protected me.
I knew as long as that
razorbeast was around,
nothing could hurt me.
You know,
over the years
his body kind of
faded away,
but the idea stayed.
And I just don't seem to talk
to him as often as I used to.
You still talk to it?
Oh, yeah.
When I'm afraid,
or I get confused
or a little scared.
I just don't think you
should have to give up
an imaginary friend.
Ensign Sutter to
Counselor Troi.
Go ahead, Ensign.
Would you come to my quarters?
I'm having a problem
with Clara.
I'm on my way.
She won't even go
into her room.
She's terrified that
Isabella's going to hurt her.
Clara?
Your father tells me that
Isabella has been saying
some very bad
things to you.
What did she say?
She said they're going
to come and kill everyone.
Who's going to come
and kill everyone?
The others, like her.
Did she say why?
I know you're very frightened.
Sometimes what we imagine
can be just as scary
as something real.
But I promise you,
there is no way
Isabella can harm you
or anyone on this ship.
But she's not
imaginary anymore.
She's real now.
I can see her.
You can see her?
Yes.
If I go with you
and hold your hand,
will you go into your room?
I think so.
We'll make sure Isabella
isn't anywhere around.
Okay?
Come on.
Do you see anybody?
Let's look under the bed.
Is she there?
Okay. Where else?
Is she behind here?
Maybe Isabella
has gone home.
Let's see.
Anything here?
Maybe Isabella knows that
you've got new friends now.
In fact, I'll bet
she doesn't come around
as much anymore.
Maybe.
What about
in the closet?
Okay.
Anybody in here?
Looks pretty
empty to me.
( gasps )
( groans )
( screams )
She was 11, maybe 12,
blonde hair.
Clara.
Clara's sleeping.
She's going
to be fine.
Her bioelectrical processes
were severely disrupted.
It's as if the energy was
pulled right out of her body.
Captain.
Clara has told me
that her imaginary friend
has been making threats.
She claimed that
others are on the way
and that they had
plans to kill
everyone on the ship.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here, sir.
Lieutenant,
we've established the presence
of what appears to be
an alien entity on board.
It seems the entity has
manifested itself
in the form of a
12-year-old human girl
who's been seen
with Clara Sutter.
She has blonde hair
and blue eyes.
WORF:
And a blue dress.
Yes, sir, I have seen her.
PICARD:
When?
Two days ago
near Engineering.
She was with Miss Sutter.
Security alert, Mr. Worf.
Keep a good lookout.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
She insisted on
talking to you.
It's about Isabella.
What about her, Clara?
I think her
feelings were hurt.
She said she liked me,
and she liked
being with me.
She was my friend.
She only got mean when I stopped
paying attention to her.
Did she say when the
others were coming?
All right, thanks, sweetie.
You go back to bed now.
We'll handle this.
But Daddy--
PICARD: Clara...
if we need your help again,
I hope we can
count on you.
Yes, Captain.
RIKER: Captain Picard,
report to the Bridge.
On my way.
Report.
Our speed is down by 22%.
Strand density is ten times
what it was, Captain.
We can't take many
more of these hits.
All stop.
Sir, something is
moving toward us.
Bearing 103,
mark 024.
On screen.
DATA: It appears to
be an energy vortex
of highly
complex patterns,
possibly a life form.
Red alert!
It is in direct physical contact
with our shields.
Shield strength
dropping to 75%.
72%.
The damn thing's feeding
off our shields.
Mr. Data, remodulate
our shield frequencies.
Aye, sir.
No effect.
Shield strength
has dropped to 64%.
We've got about eight minutes
before this thing drains
our shields.
Any ideas?
Isabella?
Don't you wanna talk to me?
I'm not mad at you.
Isabella?
We know you've been
on this ship
for some time now,
and that you're posing
as Clara's friend
and that you've
been threatening her.
We can only assume that
there is some connection
between yourself
and the life-forms
attacking this ship.
You're obviously
an intelligent being.
There's no reason
to hide from us.
Talk to us?
Or can you only communicate
by threatening a small child?
I'm scared, Isabella.
Who are you?
I came here to determine
whether you were a threat
to us, and to examine
the purity of
your energy sources.
Energy?
Is that why
you're draining our shields?
Yes.
The emissions for your
graviton field generators
are far richer than our
normal sources of energy.
Picard to Bridge.
Report.
RIKER:
Shields are down to 3%.
We're diverting all
available power.
Acknowledged.
If it's energy that you want,
we have other ways
of providing it.
You needn't destroy us.
You should be
destroyed.
You're cruel,
uncaring creatures.
What makes you say that?
The way you
treat Clara.
In what way have we
mistreated her?
You wouldn't let her
do what she wanted to,
or go where she wanted to.
You mean where
you wanted her to.
What difference
does it make?
You were taking her to places
that were inappropriate,
even dangerous.
I wouldn't have let
anything happen to her.
We didn't know that.
We didn't even know
if you were real.
All we knew was that a little
girl's imaginary friend
was frightening her,
threatening her.
That was only
after you told Clara
not to be my friend.
I understand.
You are seeing this ship,
all of us from
a unique perspective,
from a child's point of view.
It must seem
terribly unfair
and restrictive to you.
As adults, we don't
always stop to consider
how everything
we say and do shapes
the impressions
of young people.
But if you're judging us
as a people
by the way
we treat our children--
and I think there can be
no better criterion--
then you must
understand
how deeply
we care for them.
When our children
are young,
they don't understand
what might be dangerous.
Our rules are to keep them
from harm, real or imagined,
and that's part of
the continuity
of our human species.
When Clara grows up,
she will make rules
for her children
to protect them,
as we protect her.
Please, don't hurt us.
If you still wanna
be my best friend,
I'd like that very much.
Status, Number One.
We're clear of
the strands.
We'll have full warp
capability in 20 minutes.
Inform all sections
we'll be leaving this area
in one hour.
Sir?
Mr. La Forge,
I want you to drive
the warp engines to full power
and direct an energy beam
out into the nebula.
Aye, sir.
I came to say I'm sorry
I frightened you.
That's okay.
And I misled you.
I wasn't really
your Isabella.
For a while, you were.
I never had
a friend before.
I'm sorry I have
to go away.
Do you think you'll
ever come back?
I hope so.
So do I.