Captain's Log,
Stardate 45854.2.
The Enterprise is charting
six star systems
that make up
the Argolis Cluster--
an area being considered
for colonization.
Very impressive.
It's beautiful...
but frightening
at the same time.
DATA:
Captain
I am detecting a transmission
emanating
from within the system.
What sort of signal?
It is self-repeating,
of unknown pattern.
Where is it coming from?
A small moon
orbiting the
fourth planet.
Life signs?
Indeterminate.
I am attempting to screen out
sensor interference.
Readings are still inconclusive.
However, the moon's atmosphere
is capable of
supporting life.
It could be a distress call.
Helm, take us
into transport range.
Dr. Crusher, meet me
in Transporter Room Two
with a medical away team.
CRUSHER:
Acknowledged.
I'm reading one life-form,
very weak signs.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Riker to Enterprise.
PICARD:
Go ahead, Number One.
We found the wreckage
of a small craft.
One survivor.
It's a Borg.
Male, adolescent.
He's badly hurt.
DATA:
Sir, there is
no indication
of other Borg activity
within sensor range.
Away team,
prepare to return to the ship.
CRUSHER:
Captain we can't
leave him here.
He won't survive.
I think the Captain
understands that.
I don't.
The Borg
usually collect their dead.
He's not dead.
RIKER:
The transmission...
At least not yet.
The transmission
that we intercepted
was probably
a homing signal.
We have to assume
they're on their way.
Let me at least
stabilize his condition--
give him a chance of surviving
until they get here.
Your concern is noted,
Doctor
but any intervention
on our part
would alert the Borg
to our having been there.
I'm afraid we've turned
that corner already.
Kill it now.
Make it appear
that it died in the crash.
Leave no evidence
that we were ever here.
Security measures must be taken
before we beam it on board.
CRUSHER:
Thank you, Captain.
Standing by.
Mr. Data, notify security
to prepare
a detention cell.
Bridge
to Engineering.
La Forge here.
We're bringing
a Borg survivor on board.
We'll need to neutralize
the homing signal.
Prevent it from sending
or receiving transmissions
of any kind.
I'll set up a subspace
dampening field
around the detention cell.
Very well.
There are four more.
None survived.
Picard to Riker.
Go ahead, Enterprise.
We are transporting you directly
to the detention cell.
CRUSHER:
I need him in Sick Bay, Captain.
The cell, Doctor.
Whatever equipment you need
will be brought to you there.
Very well.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain,
I was wondering
if there was anything
you wanted to talk about.
I don't think
so, Counselor.
I would have thought
having a Borg on the ship
would stir some feelings.
I'm quite recovered
from my experience, thank you.
Sometimes, even when a victim
has dealt with his assault
there are residual effects
of the event that linger.
You were treated violently
by the Borg--
kidnapped, assaulted,
mutilated...
Counselor...
Counselor, I very much
appreciate your concern for me
but I can assure you,
it is quite misplaced.
I have carefully
considered the
implications
of having a Borg
on this ship.
I have weighed
the possible risks
and I'm convinced that
we are doing the right thing.
Now, I am quite comfortable
with my decision.
I see.
Well, if at any point
you want to talk more...
I shall certainly avail myself
of your help.
WORF:
Lower the force field.
Captain, the Borg
is still unconscious.
CRUSHER:
He suffered massive
internal injuries.
We've been able
to control the hemorrhaging
but some of the implants
in his brain were damaged.
I may have to
remove them.
The Borg will die
if they're removed permanently.
Their brains grow dependent
on the biochips.
Perhaps Geordi can construct
some new implants.
They contain relatively
straightforward programming--
interface protocols.
We have the files
we downloaded
after your
experience, Captain.
I think I can manage it.
Mr. La Forge...
Do you know enough
about Borg programming
to alter the pathways
to their root command structure?
I'm not sure, sir.
Subroutines are
pretty complicated.
I'd probably have to study
the data processing algorithms.
It's the only way
I could trace the access codes.
If we could get
to the root command
we could introduce
an invasive programming sequence
through its biochip system
and then return it
to the hive.
The Borg are so interconnected,
it would act like a virus.
Which would infect
the entire collective.
We could disable their
neural network at a stroke.
Infect it?
You make it sound
as if it's a disease.
Quite right, Doctor.
If all goes well,
a terminal one.
If this works the
way I think it will
once the invasive program
starts spreading
it'll only be a
matter of months
before the Borg suffer
total systems failure.
Comments?
CRUSHER:
A question.
What exactly
is total systems failure?
DATA:
The Borg are
extremely
computer-dependent.
A systems failure
will destroy them.
I just think
we should be clear about that.
We're talking about
annihilating an entire race.
PICARD:
Which under
most circumstances
would be unconscionable
but as I see it, the Borg
leave us with little choice.
I agree; we're at war.
There's been no formal
declaration of war.
Not from us,
but certainly from them.
They've attacked us
at every encounter.
They've declared war
on our way of life.
We're to be assimilated.
But even in war there are rules.
You don't kill civilians
indiscriminately.
There are no civilians
among the Borg.
Think of them
as a single collective being.
There's no one Borg
who is more an individual
than your arm or your leg.
How convenient.
PICARD:
Your point, Doctor?
When I look at my patient
I don't see a collective
consciousness.
I don't see a hive.
I see a living, breathing boy
who has been hurt
and who needs our help
and we're talking about sending
him back to his people
as an instrument of destruction.
It comes down to this--
we're faced with an enemy
who are determined to destroy us
and we have no hope
of negotiating a peace.
Unless that changes,
we are justified in doing
anything we can to survive.
Security to Captain.
Picard here.
The Borg
has regained consciousness, sir.
Acknowledged.
We proceed with the plan.
What's he doing?
He's trying to find
an access terminal
so that he can interface
with the collective.
He doesn't understand that
the signal has been cut off.
He's emitting
a homing signal
and a second
subspace beacon
but our dampening field
is blocking both signals.
He's alone.
For the first time
he's being forced to cope
with his environment
without the resources
of the collective.
He must be hungry.
The Borg don't ingest food.
Their implants can synthesize
any organic molecules
their biological tissues
require.
What they need
is energy.
Arrange to feed it.
Aye, sir.
DATA:
I'll have to adapt
a power conduit
and install it in there.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think he was scared.
( beeping )
I don't think I like this sport.
Last week when you scored
two touches
you liked it well enough.
Today, you were
dropping your foil.
You kept letting me inside.
Ah, but if I lift up
you lunge right
underneath.
Let's face it--
you're much better
at this than I am.
I understand we have
a guest on board.
Yes.
Is that wise?
I'm not sure.
I hope so.
I thought I understood you,
Picard
but I don't understand this.
It was an errand of mercy.
He was injured.
Dr. Crusher decided
for humanitarian reasons
to care for him.
They're going to come after us,
you know that.
You of all people
know that.
Shall we go again?
( sighs )
( gasps in pain )
Are you all right?
( beeping )
You felt sorry for me.
Look what it got you.
I'll have to go in
to connect the power conduit.
I will follow
the Commander.
Reactivate the field
once we're through.
Good. Now,
stay that way.
Commander!
We are Borg.
You will be
assimilated.
Resistance
is futile.
Just look around, pal.
You're hardly in a position
to make any demands.
We must return
to the collective.
Who's we?
We... are Borg.
Yeah,
but there's only one of you.
Do you have a name?
A means of identification?
Third of Five.
There were five on your ship.
Is that it?
Just a number?
Third of Five.
It does kind of suit you.
Okay.
This is for you.
It regulates the power flow
to the frequency
that you're used to.
This connection should fit
that coupling on your arm.
You're welcome.
Let's get out of here.
Lower the force field.
He's hungry, all right.
Why do you do this?
I'm just a nice guy at heart.
You feeling better?
You are not Borg.
That's right,
and I hope to stay that way.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance
is futile.
That's gratitude for you.
I've been rationing
his portions of energy.
I think he understands.
When he cooperates, he gets fed.
If not...
Like a rat in a cage.
Look, if I'm going to figure out
his command pathways
I need to learn
how he processes information
and the only way I know
how to do that
is by giving him
perceptual tests.
And for that
I need his cooperation.
So he can participate
in the destruction
of his entire species.
Doctor...
I know, I know.
We're at war.
I'm here to help,
but I don't have to like it.
Okay, I think we're ready
to transport him.
If he gives us any trouble
we can access the force field
through that console.
You ready?
La Forge
to Transporter Room Three.
We're ready here.
We're standing by, Commander.
Energize.
Third of Five,
this is Dr. Crusher.
Dr. Crusher,
this is Third of Five.
Hello.
What is a doctor?
A doctor
heals the sick
and repairs
the injured.
The sick and injured
are reabsorbed.
Others take
their place.
That isn't
what happened to you.
When we found you,
you were dying.
I saved your life.
Why?
It's my duty
to help those who are hurt.
You give us food.
Yeah.
Is that your duty?
Yeah, that's right.
Listen, Third of Five
Dr. Crusher here
has repaired
a lot of the damage to
your biochip implants.
We want to run
a few tests--
make sure everything's
working okay.
Tests?
I'd like to show you
a few diagrams
and ask you some questions
about them.
It's very simple, really.
You will be assimilated.
Yes, but before that happens
could we ask you
a few questions?
We will answer.
Terrific.
All right, hang on
just a second here,
Third of Five.
What is your designation?
Designation?
Third of Five.
You mean our names.
We don't have designations.
We have names.
I'm Beverly.
This is Geordi.
Do I have a name?
Do you want one?
A name.
I'm Beverly,
he's Geordi, and you...
You.
You...
No, wait a minute.
That's it.
Hugh.
What do you think?
You.
No, not "you"--
"Hugh."
Hugh.
Okay, now...
I'm Beverly.
I'm Geordi.
We are Hugh.
( both chuckle softly )
Now imagine what this shape
would look like
if it were turned
inside out.
Which one is it?
This one.
That's right.
He's gotten every one.
Eight out of eight.
That blows the top
right off
of the spatial acuity
percentiles.
It's the prosthetic eye.
It seems to be giving him
very complex
visual information.
Like some kind of
holographic imaging system.
That could be helpful.
Hugh, I'd like to take
a closer look at your eyepiece.
Is that okay?
Here.
Thanks.
When you are
assimilated
you will have a
similar device.
Hugh, do you understand?
We don't want
to be assimilated.
Why do you
resist us?
Because we don't want to live
the way you do.
Here it is quiet.
There are no other voices.
Other voices?
On a Borg ship
we live with the thoughts
of the others in our minds.
Thousands of voices
with us always.
I think what you're saying
is that you're lonely.
Here.
When you have
completed these tests
what will be
done with us?
We'll, um...
we'll send you home.
We will rejoin the collective.
You know, it's funny.
When I first started creating
this invasive program
I didn't have a problem
with it.
The more I work
with Hugh, the more...
Uh... Hugh?
That's what
we call him.
You named the Borg?
Well, it was easier
having something to call him.
Oh, so now you have a Borg
named Hugh.
Right, and he's nothing
like what I expected.
How so?
I don't know.
It's...
( sighs )
It's like he's just some kid
who's far away
from home.
Do you know that you are
the second person today
to refer to that Borg
as though it were
some sort of lost child?
Anyway, I'm having
second thoughts
about what we're doing here--
I mean, programming him
like some sort of walking bomb.
Sending him back to
destroy the others.
Let me tell you something.
When that "kid's" big brothers
come looking for him
they're not going to stop
till they find him
and then they're going
to come looking for us
and they will destroy us
and they will not do
any of the soul-searching
that you are apparently
doing right now.
Then why don't you
go and talk to him?
It might not be
so clear-cut then.
Because I wouldn't have
anything to say.
( sighs )
Then why don't you just listen?
That is what you do best,
isn't it?
What is it,
Number One?
We've picked up a vessel
on the long-range scanners
headed this way.
Analysis?
The vessel
is traveling at warp 7.6.
Mass: 2.5 million metric tons.
Configuration: cubical.
The Borg.
DATA:
Its dimensions indicate
that it is a scout ship
similar to the one that crashed.
Interference from
the star's radiation
will shield us
from their sensors.
We should remain undetected
until they enter the system.
How long do we have?
At present speed
they will arrive
in 31 hours, seven minutes.
You don't look so tough.
We are Borg.
Aren't you going to tell me
you have to assimilate me?
You wish to be assimilated?
No, but that's what you...
things do, isn't it?
"Resistance is futile"?
Resistance is futile.
It isn't.
My people resisted
when the Borg came
to assimilate us.
Some of us survived.
Resistance is not futile?
No.
But thanks to you,
there are very few of us left.
We are scattered
throughout the galaxy.
We don't even have
a home anymore.
What you are saying
is that you are lonely.
What?
You have no others.
You have no home.
We are also lonely.
HUGH:
What is Geordi doing?
I'm studying the
components in
your prosthesis.
Why?
I'm trying to learn
more about you.
Why?
Because you're different
than we are.
Part of what we do is learn
more about other species.
We assimilate species.
Then we know
everything about them.
Yeah. I know.
Is that not easier?
Maybe it is.
It's just not what we do.
Why?
All right.
Think of it this way.
Every time
you talk about yourself
you use the word "we."
We want this. We want that.
You don't even know
how to think of yourself
as a single individual.
You don't say,
"I want this" or "I am Hugh."
We are all
separate individuals.
I am Geordi.
I choose what I want
to do with my life.
I make decisions for myself.
For somebody like me
losing that sense
of individuality
is almost worse than dying.
When you sleep, there are
no other voices in your mind?
No.
Are you ever... lonely?
Sometimes.
But that's why we have friends.
Friends?
Sure.
Someone you can talk to
who will be with you
when you're lonely.
Someone...
( sighs )
someone
who makes you feel better.
Like Geordi... and Hugh.
That's it, Captain.
Looks harmless enough.
Well, we had to disguise it
as something innocuous.
The Borg have ways of screening
out program anomalies.
How can a geometric form
disable a computer system?
The shape is a paradox, sir.
It cannot exist
in real time or space.
When Hugh's imaging apparatus
imprints this on his biochips
he'll try to analyze it.
DATA:
He will be
unsuccessful
and will store the shape
in his memory banks.
It will be shunted to a
subroutine for further analysis.
And when the Borg
download his memory
it'll be incorporated
into their network
then they'll try to analyze it.
DATA:
It is designed
so that each step
they take will spawn
an anomalous solution.
The anomalies are designed
to interact with each other
linking together
to form an endless
and unsolvable puzzle.
Quite original.
How long
before a total systems failure?
Not until the shape
has gone through
several hundred
computational cycles.
When can you begin the process?
In about another 20 hours.
Dr. Crusher
wants to make sure
that the new implants
have taken hold.
Very well.
Begin as soon
as you're ready.
Captain...
I have to admit I've been
having second thoughts
about this plan.
In what way?
Well... I've been
getting to know him.
The Borg.
I see.
He's not what I expected,
Captain.
He's got feelings.
He's homesick.
I don't know.
It just doesn't seem right
using him this way.
Centuries ago, when
laboratory animals
were used for experiments,
scientists would sometimes
become attached
to the creatures.
This would be a problem
if the experiment
involved killing them.
I would suggest that you
un-attach yourself
from the Borg, Mr. La Forge.
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Guinan.
Please, come in.
Are you sure?
You look like
you're preparing
for a quiet evening.
No, I'm delighted to see you.
Can I get you something
to drink?
No, thank you.
I was thinking
how you said the other day
that my foil was dipping.
That I should get some exercise
and strengthen my arm.
Well, a strong forearm
is certainly an advantage
in fencing.
And bartending.
About the Borg.
Aren't you the least
bit surprised by him?
Surprised?
You know he
has a name?
La Forge gave it to him.
His name is Hugh
and he's lonely.
I don't know what
made me go see him.
La Forge said I should,
but I said no.
Then suddenly, there I was,
standing there staring at him.
I thought it was just curiosity.
Just curious.
I need to hear you say
that you are sure
you are doing the right thing.
If you are here
to persuade me
not to use
the invasive program...
No.
I think I need you
to persuade me.
Two days ago, you were so upset
about the Borg
even being on the ship
that you tore my foil
out of my hand.
And now you're here questioning
whether it should be treated
as the enemy.
I know
but when you talk to him
face-to-face
can you honestly say
you don't have any doubt?
I haven't talked to it.
Why not?
I saw no need.
If you're going
to use this person...
It's not a person, damn it!
It's a Borg.
If you are going to use
this person to destroy his race
you should at least
look him in the eye once
before you do it
because I am not sure
he is still a Borg.
Because it's been given a name
by a member of my crew
doesn't mean it's not a Borg.
Because it's young,
doesn't mean that it's innocent.
It is what it is
and in spite of efforts
to turn it into some kind of pet
I will not alter my plans.
Fine.
But if you don't talk to him
at least once
you may find that decision
a lot harder to live with
than you realize.
Worf to Captain Picard.
Yes, Lieutenant.
We are ready to transport.
Proceed.
Lieutenant,
you may wait outside.
Locutus.
Yes.
I am Locutus of Borg.
Why are you here?
This is a primitive culture.
I am here to facilitate
its incorporation.
Identify yourself.
Hugh.
We are Hugh.
This is not
a Borg identification.
Third of Five.
This culture
will be assimilated.
They do not wish it.
Irrelevant.
They will resist us.
Resistance is futile.
Resistance is not futile.
Some have escaped.
They will be found.
It is inevitable.
All will be assimilated.
Must Geordi be assimilated?
Yes.
He does not wish it.
He would rather die
than be assimilated.
Then he will die.
No.
Geordi must not die.
Geordi is a friend.
You will assist us
to assimilate this vessel.
You are Borg.
You will assist us.
I will not.
What did you say?
I will not assist you.
I?
Geordi must not be assimilated.
But you are Borg.
No.
I am Hugh.
I think that I deliberately
avoided meeting with the Borg
because I didn't want anything
to get in the way of our plan.
But now that I have...
he seems to be
a fully realized...
individual.
He's even accepted me
as Picard
Captain
of this ship
and not
as Locutus.
So, you've reconsidered
the plan?
Yes. To use him in this manner,
we'd be no better
than the enemy
that we seek to destroy.
So, I want other options.
RIKER:
We could return him
to the crash site.
We'd have to remove his memory
of having been
on the Enterprise.
But if we erase
his memory
who he is or who he has become
would be destroyed.
Isn't that the point?
He'd be reassimilated
back into the hive
without any questions.
Does that seem right--
to help him become
an individual
and then take that
away from him?
Is there any danger
that the Borg
might destroy him
if they find out
what's happened?
PICARD:
I doubt it.
There'd be nothing to gain.
It's more likely that
they would simply wipe out
his memory of those experiences.
Then either way, his memory
would have been erased.
But perhaps...
in that short time
before they purge his memory...
the sense of individuality
which he has gained with us
might be transmitted through
the entire Borg collective.
Every one of the Borg
being given the opportunity
to experience the feeling
of... of singularity.
And perhaps that's the most
pernicious program of all--
the knowledge of self
being spread
throughout the collective
in that brief moment
might alter them forever.
We leave his memory intact.
I have a question.
What if he doesn't want
to go back?
Hello, Hugh.
Hello, Geordi.
Hugh, a Borg rescue vessel
is approaching.
It will be here
within three hours.
We can return you
to the crash site
where they will find you
and then take you home
or if you wish,
you can stay here with us.
What I wish is irrelevant.
It's not irrelevant, Hugh.
It matters to us.
No Borg
leaves the collective.
If they find I am missing,
they will come for me.
Well, we'll deal with
the repercussions later.
We must know what you want.
You are many.
I am one.
What I want is not important.
Don't you understand, Hugh?
We're giving you a choice.
Choice...
Yes, a choice.
Do you want to go back
with the Borg
or stay with us?
I could stay with you?
We could grant you asylum, Hugh.
Choose what I want.
I would choose
to stay with Geordi.
But it is too dangerous.
They will follow.
Return me to the crash site.
It is the only way.
Hugh, think about this.
Are you sure?
Yes.
The Borg ship will
enter orbit in one hour.
You'll soon
be headed home.
We'll beam him down and then
we'll take up a position
in the star's chromosphere.
The interference
will hide us
from their sensors.
Good-bye, Hugh.
It was nice
getting to know you.
Good-bye, Beverly.
You saved my life.
Hugh, it's not too late
to change your mind.
I must return.
Captain, I'd like
to go down with him.
My experience suggests
that they would ignore him.
Would you agree?
The Borg assimilate
civilizations, not individuals.
But, Captain,
they kidnapped you.
Because they needed a liaison
to communicate with humans.
They ignored every away team
we sent to their ship
including yours, Doctor.
You may accompany him.
Good-bye.
Captain, I do not want to forget
that I am Hugh.
Energize.
We found you there,
in the middle of that debris.
Then that is
where I will wait.
We are now
entering position.
Radiation levels
are rising.
Increase power
to the shields.
Hold us here.
Status of the Borg ship?
Solar radiation is rendering
our sensors inoperable.
At last known course and speed
the Borg vessel should enter
the system in three minutes.
Well, I guess
this is it, huh?
So long, Hugh.
Good-bye, Geordi.
I will try
to remember you.