Time, Mr. Data?
We will arrive
within transporter range
in three minutes, 21 seconds.
I've finally established
audio contact
with the Romulan ship.
ROMULAN:
Our main power is failing.
There is no way
to stop the overload.
Enterprise
to Romulan vessel.
We are en route
to your position.
ROMULAN: Enterprise,
what is your time of arrival?
We are facing an imminent
core breach...
Repeat your
last transmission.
I'm sorry, Captain.
They've stopped transmitting.
Picard to Riker.
Riker here.
PICARD: Transport to
the Romulan ship as soon
as we're within range.
Aye, sir.
No weapons.
We don't want them to think
they're under attack.
This is not
a bright idea.
I beg your pardon,
Ensign?
I didn't quite catch that.
Nothing, sir.
( inaudible chatter )
We're from the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
We received your distress call.
The Enterprise?
RIKER: That's right.
Your message said you had
suffered a failure
in your engine core.
ROMULAN: Yes, we had a
forced chamber explosion
in the resonator coil.
It's a pretty strange setup
but it looks like
the graviton field generator's
been completely depolarized.
There's no way to fix it.
It'll have to be replaced.
Where are your replicators?
They're off-line.
Who's in charge here?
The captain is dead.
I'm the Science Officer Mirok.
We'd like to move
this generator
back to the Enterprise
for replication.
All right.
Geordi, you and Ro.
La Forge to Brossmer.
Two people and one piece
of equipment to beam aboard.
Aye, sir.
What the hell?
Engineering, I need more power
to the primary
energizing coil.
Brossmer to Commander Riker.
I'm losing them.
I have to abort.
They should be returning
to your coordinates, sir.
Chief, do you have them?
They're not here.
BROSSMER:
No, sir.
Where are they?
I can't locate their patterns.
We've lost them, sir.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
BROSSMER:
I've done all I can, sir.
I'm afraid they're gone.
Mr. Data, begin
a level-one diagnostic.
All transporter systems
off-line until further notice.
Could they have materialized
somewhere else?
Negative, Captain.
Sensors are unable
to locate them
anywhere within
transporter range.
Counselor?
Riker to Enterprise.
Go ahead,
Number one.
Captain, we're still
looking at a core breach
unless we can fashion
a new graviton generator.
I need replacement
personnel, sir.
Mr. Data,
continue the diagnostic
of the transporter systems
at another time.
Take a shuttlecraft
and two more engineers
down to the Romulan ship.
Aye, sir.
Mr. McDowell, alert
the main shuttle bay
to have all available ships
and pilots standing by
in case we need them.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, lay in a course
away from the Romulan vessel,
And engage at warp one
if you detect any sign
it's going to explode.
The pressure in the
containment chamber
has increased 15 melakols
in the last two minutes.
What can we do
to stop the overload?
Most of the conduits
were damaged
during the explosion.
I can't even access
the central computer.
WORF:
Commander...
emergency bulkheads have
sealed this section off
from the rest of the ship.
There is no way to gain
access to the Main Bridge
or control centers.
Survivors?
Readings indicate at least
73 Romulans are still alive.
73.
( alarm sounding )
The pressure has jumped
200 melakols!
I've lost control of the
containment chamber.
It's going to implode.
We need to dump the entire
engine core.
Do you have
an auto-eject system?
Yes, but it's
not functioning.
I'll have to
do it manually.
Mr. Worf, you two,
seal the chambers.
Implosion will occur in
one minute, five seconds.
Enterprise, we need to jettison
the entire engine core.
You'll need to
extend the shields
once it clears the hull.
PICARD:
Understood, Number One.
We'll stand by for your signal.
We must get
the doors closed.
( grunting )
Commander!
Time?
30 seconds.
( grunting )
MIROK:
I'm ready, Commander!
Stay there!
Eject the chamber
on my order!
Excuse me, sir.
MIROK:
Implosion in five seconds.
Now.
Enterprise,
extend shields!
Well...
we're still here.
Yes.
RIKER: We'll have a
complete power survey
done within the hour.
We'll probably
have to supply them
with energy for life-support,
they'll need a new engine core
to get home.
Understood, Commander.
Keep me informed
of your efforts.
Picard out.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Ro to the Bridge.
This is Ensign Ro
reporting in.
I'm at... Section 23 Baker,
near Sick Bay.
Sick Bay.
Excuse me,
I need some... help.
Excuse me.
Um, excuse me,
I need some help.
I...
Excuse me,
I need some help.
CRUSHER: We shouldn't make any
hasty decisions, Jean-Luc.
The transporter could have
beamed them somewhere else--
the Romulan ship, another deck
of the Enterprise.
PICARD: We've checked
all those possibilities.
The initial findings
would seem to indicate
that there was
a radiation surge
from the Romulan engine core
which disrupted the signal.
They never rematerialized.
We should check again.
There might be something
that we overlooked--
Beverly, we've done
everything that we can.
You're right.
I just hate making out
death certificates.
CRUSHER: Does Ensign Ro
have any family?
Captain, I'm right here.
None that I know of.
But I'll check with the
Bajoran Liaison Office.
I'm not dead!
I'll have
the official reports
ready within the hour.
Captain, I don't know
what's going on.
( gasps )
Doctor?
Dr. Crusher?
Dr. Crusher, I'm right here.
Damn it, Doc...
( gasps )
We're ready, Commander.
Riker to Enterprise.
Begin power transfer.
The power flow is consistent
at 400 kolems.
No fluctuations
in frequency.
The main power grid is on-line.
Picard to Riker.
Riker here.
Power transfer appears
stable on this end, Captain.
Good. What is the status of
the engine replacement?
RIKER:
Engineering is modifying
one of our subspace
resonators
to act as a new engine core.
It won't do more than warp two,
but it will get them home.
Very good.
Captain, the diagnostic
of the transporter system
shows an anomalous
energy fluctuation.
I will need to inspect
the imaging scanner
in Transporter Room Three.
By all means.
Captain...
I have a personal
favor to ask.
I considered Commander La Forge
to be... my best friend.
I believe it is my
responsibility
to plan and conduct
the memorial service.
May I have your permission
to do so?
Permission granted.
Make whatever arrangements
you think are appropriate.
Thank you, sir.
( crew chattering )
Commander, the...
the Romulans
want a computer.
We cannot give them access
to Federation technology.
That is an
unacceptable security risk.
What about a computer core
from 30 or 40 years ago?
One the Romulans are
already familiar with.
That would be satisfactory.
Check with the Enterprise.
See what's available.
But be sure that your
concerns are addressed
before we install it.
Aye, sir.
Thank you.
RO:
La Forge?
Ro.
Boy, am I glad
to see you.
And I'm really glad
that you can see me.
It's like...
it's like I'm here,
but I'm not here.
No one can see me
either.
( sighs )
I can't figure it out.
One minute we were transporting
from the Romulan vessel
and the next
I wake up
in the arboretum
with a splitting headache.
Can you pass through
things like bulkheads?
Tables, people...
yeah.
Well, we're solid
enough to each other.
It's not what
you expected, is it?
( sighs )
What do you mean?
This.
Death.
What?
We're dead, Geordi.
Is that some
kind of a joke?
Our patterns were lost in
a transporter malfunction.
We never rematerialized after
leaving the Romulan ship.
Wait a minute.
What are you saying--
that we're some sort
of spirits?
Spirits, souls...
my people used to
call them "borhyas."
But whatever term you
wanna use, we're it.
But my uniform, my visor.
Are you saying I'm some
blind ghost with clothes?
I don't have all the answers.
I've never been dead before.
We are not dead.
According to Dr. Crusher
we died
in a transporter malfunction
at 1430 hours.
Geordi, I saw her make out
the death certificates.
We need to make peace
with our former lives.
That's what I was taught.
We have to say good-bye
to the people
who were in our lives.
No, you may be ready
for the afterlife
but I'm not.
I don't see that we have
much of a choice.
( sighs )
When I was growing up,
I never gave much thought
to all the talk about borhyas.
I figured that
it was just superstition
passed on to children.
Fine, you go make peace
with yourself, all right?
I'm going to
Transporter Room Three.
I'm gonna figure a way
out of this situation.
I didn't have any warning
that something
would go wrong, sir.
Suddenly, their patterns
just weren't there.
I believe the cause
of the accident
may be related to the
explosion on the Romulan ship.
Really?
But that happened
before we even arrived.
In all likelihood,
the explosion
damaged the Romulan
cloaking device,
causing it to discharge
chroniton particles.
I am detecting
a chroniton field in here.
Chroniton field?
If the particles were
produced on the Romulan ship,
why are you detecting
them here?
The transporter beam.
I suspect they traveled
through the transporter beam.
That may have been the cause
of Geordi and Ro's death.
I will go to
the Romulan ship.
Perhaps I can discover the
source of the emissions.
Commander, are these
chronitons dangerous?
They pose no danger
to humans.
However, some of the ship's
systems may have been affected
by prolonged exposure.
When I return, I will devise
a method to eradicate them.
La Forge to Ensign...
Thanks for the ride.
I'm here to say good-bye.
There were a lot
of what appeared to be
experimental engine components
lying around over there.
I'd say they were testing
a new warp drive design
and it blew up
in their faces.
PICARD: That would explain
why they're so far
from Romulan space--
to avoid being picked up
by Federation long-range scans.
We should have an engine core
ready for them by 1900 hours.
Commander, there will be
a memorial service
at 2300 hours.
Mr. Data is making
the arrangements.
I'll be there.
Me too.
In fact, I might like
to say a few words.
You did know La Forge
longer than any of us.
Actually, I was thinking
more about Ensign Ro.
Me?
PICARD: When you're ready,
coordinate with Mr. Data.
Wait a minute, what are you
gonna say about me?
Captain...
I don't believe this.
I'm dead.
You can't even hear me,
and I'm still
intimidated by you.
I just... wanted to
say thank you...
for trusting in me
when no one else would.
Hey, there you are.
Excuse me, Captain.
Listen, Data's taking the
next shuttle back over
to the Romulan vessel,
and we need to be on it.
Why?
Because I think what
happened to us,
the answers
are over there.
Why can't you just
accept the fact--
Look, if you're right,
then we're dead
and this doesn't make
any difference.
But if I'm right,
then we're still alive,
and I'm gonna
need your help.
Lieutenant, I am planning
a memorial service
for Commander La Forge
and Ensign Ro.
I would like you
to participate.
What kind of service?
Captain Picard asked me
to arrange a ceremony
that was appropriate.
I have given
a great deal of thought
to what is appropriate
in this instance.
Sir, shuttlecraft four
has not yet cleared
the Romulan ship.
Hold position here.
This is weird
listening to them
plan our funeral.
I find I am having
difficulty
deciding what kind
of service to have.
Do you have
any suggestions?
Well, human custom is to conduct
a solemn, dignified service
in which the dead are praised
by their friends and loved ones.
Ensign Ro was a Bajoran.
Her beliefs should be
reflected as well.
However, their death rituals
are quite complicated.
Oh, please,
not the death chant.
The Bajoran death chant
is over two hours long.
I am not certain
that either human or
Bajoran rights are fitting.
And I have researched
the funerary customs
of over 5,000 cultures
to no avail.
( alert beep )
Shuttlecraft four
has just cleared.
Resume course.
In almost all societies
it is traditional
to say a ritual farewell
to those you call friends.
I never knew what a friend was
until I met Geordi.
He spoke to me
as though I were human.
He treated me no differently
from anyone else.
He accepted me
for what I am.
And that, I have learned,
is friendship.
But I do not know
how to say good-bye.
Seems almost human,
doesn't he?
Commander, I am not the proper
person to advise you.
Why?
I am very happy for
Commander La Forge.
He has crossed over
to that which is beyond.
For a Klingon,
this is a joyful time.
A friend has died
in the line of duty,
and he has earned a place
among the honored dead.
It is not a time to mourn.
( alert beeping )
Begin docking procedure.
Data, that's
a nice sentiment
but a little premature.
I don't plan on being
commemorated before my time.
I'm afraid I fail
to see the point
of this investigation,
Commander.
Chroniton emissions
may have been responsible
for the accident which claimed
the lives of our officers.
A most regrettable
event, of course.
Was your cloaking device
damaged in the explosion?
All of our systems
were damaged,
including
the cloaking device.
That explains
the chroniton fields
I am detecting in here now.
For your own safety,
it is important to
eliminate those emissions.
Our safety?
There is no way to
predict what will happen
when the chronitons interact
with the new engine core.
I've never seen
anything like this.
There's something
in here
that looks like
a molecular phase inverter.
What's that?
It's supposed to change
the structure of matter
so it can pass through
normal matter and energy.
Hang on a second.
A few years back,
we got intelligence reports
that the Klingons
were working on
trying to combine
a phase inverter
and a cloaking device.
In theory, they believed
that a phased ship
could hide anywhere,
even inside a planet
and that conventional weapons
would be useless against it.
How far did they get
in their research?
Well, it never got out
of the preliminary stages.
There were several
accidents.
The Romulans might be
pursuing that same technology,
trying to combine an inverter
and a cloaking device.
And if this is
the prototype--
Then that would explain
the explosion
and the chroniton fields.
And us.
You mean, we're cloaked?
Not just cloaked-- phased.
Our entire
molecular structure
altered so that we--
we don't have any substance.
Then that would mean
we're not dead.
Yes, it would also mean
that there's probably
a way to de-phase us.
Field emissions are
particularly strong
in this area.
You can be assured
that the emissions
will be eliminated
before the engine core
is replaced.
WORF:
Commander, may I speak with you?
If they come back,
they're going to discover
the interphase generator.
Is their power transfer beam
still at full intensity?
Yes, it will be
until we're ready to
switch to internal power.
We will set up
a muon feedback wave
inside the transfer beam.
The particles will accumulate
in their dilithium chamber.
When they go to warp speed,
their engines will explode.
We've gotta get to the
Enterprise and warn them.
How?
I don't know,
but we have to find a way.
Come on.
The muon feedback wave's
not showing up
on any of the
engine displays.
The Romulans
must be hiding it
in the sensory
return signal.
Unless someone runs
a level three diagnostic
they'd never detect it.
There must be
some way to warn them
before the ship
goes into warp.
This is puzzling.
Three more chroniton fields
have formed
aboard the Enterprise
in the last hour.
There's no reason why
the interphase device
would be producing
new fields onboard this ship.
We should begin
decontamination immediately.
Run an internal
sensor sweep
for the locations
of all chroniton fields
on the Enterprise.
Aye, sir.
The following areas
are showing contamination.
Sick Bay,
Transporter Room Three,
Main Bridge,
Captain's Ready Room,
Shuttlebay Two
and Main Engineering.
Ro, take a look
at this.
DATA:
I do not understand
how these new fields
have formed.
No transporter beam
has been active
in any of those areas.
And I cannot see they have
anything in common.
Oh, yes they do.
In fact, they seem to be
appearing at random.
No, they're not!
We were in every one
of those locations.
Somehow, we're leaving
chroniton footprints behind us.
Can you narrow the focus
of the scan
to pinpoint the locations?
Not with the internal
sensors, Commander.
Go to Science Station Two
on the Main Bridge.
Use a lateral sensor array
to get a more
precise reading.
I will modify an anyon emitter
to eliminate the fields
once they've been isolated.
Why don't you
go with her
and see what
the lateral sensor turn up?
I'm gonna stay here
with Data.
Right.
( alert beeping )
Well, that's interesting.
You're reading
chroniton fields in here
but not from me?
There's a field
in this wall? Why?
Data, I came through
this wall.
I walked right through it
when I came in here.
When the phase matter
in my body
passed through the wall,
it must have disrupted
the wall's molecular structure
producing
a chroniton field.
( alert beeping )
Data, I'm right here.
That's me you're reading.
Watch.
( alert beeping )
LA FORGE:
Come on.
It's me!
( alert beeping )
You see?
Do not move.
Yes...
I can see you.
Who are you?
Where is
the scientific officer?
The one like us.
The one who came with you
to our ship.
He spoke of a plan
to return to normal.
Yes, this disruptor works.
I was wearing it
when I was changed.
Now, where is he?
( alert beeping )
Data, stop being
so rational.
Try using your imagination
once in a while.
These aren't just
random patterns,
It's me!
Ahh!
Watch where you point
that thing.
Wait a minute, Data.
I think you did something here.
It's not so easy
to push through anymore.
The molecules in my hand
must have been partially
de-phased by the anyon beam.
Data, if
a low-level beam
can bring my hand
part of the way back,
maybe a high-level beam can
bring me all the way back.
I'll just have to get you
to turn up the intensity so...
Hey, wait a minute.
Don't stop now.
No, no, no, no.
Data, don't give up on it.
It works.
I was just creating
more fields.
Your method is fine.
You just need to turn up
the intensity, Data.
( sighs )
He's in here.
Brossmer to Commander Data.
Data here.
BROSSMER: I've just detected
a large chroniton field
on Deck 17.
The field strength is 300% above
the others we've found, sir.
Is that Ro?
Acknowledged.
( alert beeping )
( groans )
( beeping intensifies )
Get up!
Where is the science officer?
( door chimes )
( grunts )
MAN: I'll get it.
Commander!
Excuse me, Lieutenant--
Ro!
I'm detecting
a chroniton field
in your room.
May I scan the area?
MAN:
Certainly.
Thanks.
Any time.
There's still no indication
that the Romulans
have set up a muon wave
in our dilithium chamber.
It's there, and when
they go to warp--
MCDOWELL: Incoming message from
the Romulan ship, Captain.
On screen.
Now what?
MIROK: Installation of the new
engine core has been completed.
We are ready to switch to
internal power, Enterprise.
Understood.
Disconnect
the power transfer beam.
MIROK:
We are now on internal power.
Captain Picard, please accept
my sincere thanks
on behalf of the Romulan Empire.
Don't listen
to him, Captain.
It was our pleasure, Mirok.
And I hope that this
example of cooperation
between our two peoples
will not be
an isolated incident.
As do I, Captain.
Set a course for the
Garadius system, warp six.
Don't do it, sir!
Captain, wait, don't!
BROSSMER: Captain,
I'm still running
the decontamination program.
Mr. Data believes we shouldn't
engage the warp drive
until I've cleared all the
chroniton fields from the ship.
Very well, let me know
when you finish your sweep.
Yes, sir.
If we can get
to the locations
that she's decontaminating,
maybe the anyon emissions
would re-phase us enough
for someone to see us.
Yeah, well, the beam strength
will have to be pretty strong
in order for us
to be visible
for more than
a millisecond.
Somebody's gonna have to
be looking directly at us.
Then we're gonna
have to go somewhere
with an awful lot
of people.
It's time, sir.
We should go.
You have the Bridge,
Mr. McDowell.
I'll be at the
service in Ten Forward.
Ten Forward?
Well, that's perfect.
We'll create as many
chroniton fields
in there as we can,
get them to flood that room
with a stronger beam.
PICARD:
Deck ten.
I've been thinking
about the first time
I met Geordi La Forge.
He was a young officer
assigned to pilot me
on an inspection tour,
and I made some
offhand remark
about the... shuttle's
engine efficiency
not being
what it should.
And the next morning
I found that he'd stayed up
all night refitting
the fusion initiators.
Well, I knew then that
I wanted to have him
with me on my
next command.
Have you decided what you're
gonna say about Ensign Ro?
Yes, I have.
Wasn't easy.
Situations like these...
What?
...are never easy,
Number One.
What wasn't easy?
( Dixieland band playing )
What?!
( band playing,
people chattering )
What is going on here?
It's our
memorial service.
This?
Why not?
I don't believe this.
They think we're dead
and they're having a party?
( chuckles )
Yeah. It's perfect.
Come on,
let's get started.
Well, this is... unusual.
Yeah.
I think I like it.
( begins playing trombone )
Now, I suppose
I'll never know
what you were gonna
say about me.
Do you think the others will
find this service appropriate?
Look around you, Data.
Everybody's sharing
their memories
of Geordi and Ro,
laughing and talking.
What could be more
appropriate than that?
I am glad you approve.
Brossmer to Commander Data.
Go ahead, Chief.
BROSSMER: I'm sorry
to disturb you, sir.
We've cleared the critical
areas of chronitons,
but we've detected a new
field forming in Ten Forward
that's stronger than any
we've seen before.
Should I wait till
after the service is over
before beginning
decontamination?
No, anyon emissions
are harmless.
Please begin
immediately.
BROSSMER:
Aye, sir.
Here we go.
( grunting )
Worf...
Worf, can you see us?
Lieutenant?
We're right here, Worf.
( scoffs )
Damn.
We have to find
a way to increase
the emission strength.
Yeah, I know.
If she hadn't lost
her rank as a result
of that incident at Garon IV,
I think she would have made
lieutenant commander by now.
MCDOWELL:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead.
MCDOWELL: Incoming message
from Garadius IV, sir.
The diplomatic situation
is deteriorating.
They want an
update on our ETA.
Stand by, Ensign.
Excuse me.
We have to do something now
before they go into warp.
The disruptor-- I can
put it on overload.
Do it.
Let's go.
I would like to get
underway as soon as possible.
The situation on Garadius IV
is becoming serious.
I see no reason to
delay our departure.
The chroniton fields
have been cleared
from all critical areas.
Excellent.
Mr. McDowell, will you
set a course
for Garadius IV
and engage--
BROSSMER: Commander data,
chroniton field strength
in Ten Forward has just
increased by 3,000%.
Curious.
Captain, I believe we
should decontaminate
this room before
getting underway.
Very well.
Chief?
BROSSMER:
Yes, Commander?
Increase
anyon emissions
to 6,000 particles
per second
and decontaminate
this area.
Okay, hang on.
Data, Data, do you see us?
Captain!
We're right here!
Do you see that,
Mr. Data?
Yes, sir.
Come on, Data, put it
all together now.
Those were not ghosts.
What did we see?
I believe I may know
what has happened, sir.
Oh, Data,
please, be right!
It would explain the mysterious
chroniton fields...
Yes, yes, yes!
...if they were
cloaked in some way.
Are you saying that
they're still alive?
If I am right,
sir, they are,
and in this room.
Their brief appearance
coincided
with the anyon sweep.
Perhaps the anyons
neutralized
the cloaking effect.
Chief Brossmer.
BROSSMER: Yes, Commander?
Set the anyonic beam
to its highest level
and flood Ten Forward.
BROSSMER:
Aye, sir.
Data, do you see us?
Of course.
La Forge to Engineering. Take
the warp engines
off-line until
further notice.
There's a muon wave building up
inside the dilithium chamber.
MCDOWELL:
Captain, who gave that order?
That was Commander
Geordi La Forge, Ensign.
Please follow his
instructions.
MCDOWELL:
Aye, sir.
Well, it looks like
a great party.
You mind if
we join you?
( crowd murmuring )
Geordi, it is good
to see you.
Thanks, Data.
I've never been to
a better funeral.
Mm, could you
pass the rolls?
You've been eating
for over an hour.
Come on.
We didn't eat for
almost two days.
I'm hungry.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Come on.
I was raised with
Bajoran beliefs
and I even followed
some of the practices.
But I never really believed
in a life after death.
And then suddenly,
I was dead,
and there was
this other life,
And it made me feel like
I'd been pretty arrogant
to discount everything
I'd been taught, you know?
Now, I don't know
what to believe.
Hmm, well...
maybe we should develop
our own interphase device.
If it can teach
Ro Laren humility...
it can do anything.
( both laughing )