Captain's Log,
Stardate 45944.1.
Following a magnetic wave
survey of the Parvenium system
we have detected an object
which we cannot
immediately identify.
Magnify.
Mr. Data?
It appears to be
a probe of some kind,
but there is no
starfleet record of
this shape or design.
Is it scanning us?
No, sir, but it has assumed
a relative position
and is holding
course with us.
The probe is composed of
paricium and talgonite--
a ceramic alloy.
Not a very
sophisticated technology.
Sir, I am detecting
a low-level nucleonic beam
coming from the probe.
Shields up.
Stand by phasers.
The beam is scanning
the shield's perimeter.
The probe is emitting
an unusual particle stream.
Sir, the beam is
penetrating our shields.
Increase speed to...
Captain?
It's all right.
Captain, I've got you.
It's all...
Well, finally.
How are you feeling?
Kamin?
Can you answer me?
What is this place?
Oh, you're still feverish.
Computer, freeze program.
Computer, end program.
Kamin...
Picard to Enterprise...
Kamin,
please don't get up yet.
You're still not well.
I asked you,
what is this place?
This is your home,
of course.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Am I a prisoner here?
Please, dear, you've had
a high fever for three days.
You mustn't push yourself
too quickly.
Kamin...
you really shouldn't
go outside.
Kamin...
please come back inside.
( applause )
Thank you.
This sapling is planted
as an affirmation of life
in defiance of the drought.
And with expectations
of long life.
Whatever comes,
we will keep it alive as
a symbol of our survival.
Kamin, you're
back on your feet.
How do you feel, my friend?
Are you in charge here?
In charge?
I want to be returned
to my ship immediately.
What ship is that?
Please...
Just tell me,
what is this place?
Where am I?
The fever.
It's taken your memory.
That must be it.
Perhaps you can help me.
Anything, my friend.
My name is Kamin.
Yes.
And you are...?
Batai.
Council leader Batai.
Ah...
Batai.
You say I've been ill?
For more than a week.
Eline should have
put you in the hospital
but she insisted
on caring for you herself.
Eline?
Your wife.
If you don't remember
that, maybe it's
safer not to go home.
And, uh...
what is this place?
Perhaps you should
see the doctor.
No.
Please... I'm sure it
will all come back to me.
This is the community
of Ressik,
northern province.
What planet?
Let me take you
back home.
No, really,
I'm quite all right.
Just answer me:
what planet?
This is the planet Kataan.
Kataan...
not a Federation planet.
I, uh, think I'll...
I'll just take a walk.
But you've been ill
for a week.
The exercise
will do me good.
I'll, uh, try to
reacquaint myself
with the surroundings.
( knocking at the door )
Thank goodness.
I've had people out, trying
to find you everywhere.
Why did you worry us
like that?
Are you hungry?
Hungry, thirsty,
exhausted.
I suppose that proves
this is not a dream...
doesn't it?
You think that this--
your life-- is a dream?
This is not my life.
I know that much.
I've kept something
hot for you.
Where did you go?
I walked... for hours.
And you,
just out of bed.
This is delicious.
You always say that.
Would you try to answer
some questions for me,
no matter how strange
they may seem to you?
Of course.
Are there any other planets
in this star system?
Do you visit other systems?
All right.
Um... do you have
a communication system here?
How do you...
how do you send messages
to other communities--
other places?
The usual way-- by
voice transit conductor.
Do you want to
send a message?
Mm-hmm, yes.
Um, when can that
be arranged?
Tomorrow.
Don't you want
to ask about us?
Of course.
Um... anything you can
tell me will be helpful.
We, um...
we, um...
we're married.
Three years ago.
The happiest day of my life
was the day we got married.
And what do I do
here in Ressik?
You're the best iron weaver
in the community--
at least I think so.
You prefer playing
the flute, of course.
The flute?
Yes.
When did I learn
to play this?
I'm afraid
you never did, dear.
You do keep trying.
I see what you mean.
Well, thank you
for the soup.
And thank you
for your help.
Tomorrow, will you help
me to send a message?
Of course.
Now, will you
come to bed?
Oh, I'll sleep here.
Kamin, please come
with me.
I've been sick.
I'll be tossing
and turning.
It wouldn't be
fair to you.
Let me be the judge
of that.
Where did you get this?
Kamin, this is the first
gift you ever gave me.
Riker to sick bay.
The captain's hurt.
Pulse and blood pressure
are normal.
I'm getting hyperactive
fibrogenic activity.
This is odd.
What is it?
There's no evidence
of any injury or trauma.
Vital signs are normal but
neurotransmitter production
is off the scale.
What's going on?
This probe is doing
something to him.
Anything yet, Data?
No, sir.
The particle
emission is most unusual.
I am unable to block it.
We should destroy the probe.
Phasers are armed and ready.
I don't think that's wise--
not until we know exactly
what it's doing to him.
Agreed. Stand down
phasers, Mr. Worf.
In the meantime, take us
out of range, Ensign.
Thrusters only, 100 kph.
Nice and easy.
Aye, sir.
Data?
The probe is moving
with us, sir, holding
relative position.
It's connected itself
to him like a tether.
You've been dreaming
about that starship of
yours again, haven't you?
I'm just charting
the progress of the
course of the sun.
Might give a clue to the
cause of this drought.
I think you're still trying
to figure out where you are,
where that ship of yours is,
how to get back
to that life.
The memory
is five years old now...
but it's still inside me.
Was your life there so
much better than this?
So much more gratifying?
So much more fulfilling
that you cling to it
with such stubbornness?
Eline...
It must have been
extraordinary,
but never, in all the
stories you've told me,
have you mentioned anyone
who loved you as I do.
( sighs )
It was real.
It was
as real as this is.
And you can't expect me
to forget a lifetime
spent there.
Yes, I can.
I've been patient, Kamin.
For five years,
I've shared you
with that other life.
I've listened,
I've tried to understand,
and I have waited.
When do I get you back?
I know.
It has been hard
on you.
When will you let go?
When will you start
living this life?
When will we start
a family?
BATAI:
Kamin.
Eline.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Batai.
Are you ready?
The administrator's
already arrived.
Yes.
Will you come along?
No, thank you.
You do very well
on your own.
She always was
strong-minded,
even as a child.
It's not her fault.
These past few years
have been very
difficult for her.
And for you, I think.
There you are, Batai.
Perhaps you can
explain to me,
when crops are dying
all over, how this tree
is flourishing.
This tree is our symbol,
our affirmation of life.
Everyone in this town gives
part of their water rations
to keep it alive.
We've learned,
Administrator,
that hope is a powerful
weapon against anything,
even drought.
A good point.
Perhaps I shall recommend
a symbolic tree in each
of my communities.
Now, what business
do we have today?
We need help if we're
to increase the water supply.
We think there are ways
to reclaim some of our water.
Batai, you're being
a bit of an alarmist.
True, we are in a drought,
but water rationing has
produced a sizeable savings.
If the weather pattern
doesn't change,
rationing will not be enough--
we'll run out of water.
Who is this?
Kamin, sir.
Kamin.
Do I know you?
No. I haven't spoken
to you before.
Well, Kamin, I'm open to
all the people of this town.
I'm delighted to hear
what you have to say.
I suggest that we build
atmospheric condensers
which could extract
water from the air.
I don't mean to quash
your very creative ideas,
but building
atmospheric condensers
would be
a monumental undertaking.
We could not hope
to sustain such a project.
Each community will be
responsible for its own.
Condensers could
make the difference
between watering our crops
and watching them die.
Well, I'll be glad
to pass along your idea.
You'll see that this kind
of participatory government
works for everyone.
Be well, Batai. I shall
see you next month.
Good to meet you...
Kamin.
BATAI:
Go carefully,
Administrator.
That went very well.
I think he was
impressed with you.
There will be no
atmospheric condensers.
Well, these things take
time, but it will happen.
I'm sure of it.
Come and have supper
tonight, old friend.
I'll make
some vegetable stew.
Let's talk about building
our own condenser, hmm?
Kamin...
hearing you talk
to the administrator,
I realized that
for the first time in years
you were speaking
as though you were truly
a member of the community.
It was good to
hear that again.
( flute playing )
You've been brooding
behind that flute all evening.
I'm not brooding.
I'm immersed in my music.
Music.
I find that it helps me
to think.
But the real surprise is--
I enjoy it so much.
No, the real surprise
is that you may actually
be improving.
Batai.
Yes, ma'am.
Go home.
Good night, Kamin.
Good night, my friend.
Go carefully, Batai.
Don't forget these.
I won't put them away
for you again.
Yes, ma'am.
I've done nothing
but nag all day.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm the one
who's sorry.
Everything you said
this morning was
absolutely correct.
I feel that I have
given you so little
and you have given me
so much.
No.
You're a good man,
a wonderful husband.
I didn't mean...
No, not such
a wonderful husband.
I spend my spare time
charting the stars,
disappear for days at a time
exploring the countryside.
My life is very much
as it was.
Old habits.
You're gentle and kind.
You never once
raised your voice to me.
I'd like to ask
your permission
to build something.
Kamin, you've built
your telescope,
your laboratory.
You don't need
my permission
for something new.
In this case,
I think I do.
What is it?
A nursery.
Really?
Unless, of course, if
you would prefer a porch,
it would certainly
be much easier to build
and I could make
a start on it right away.
No, no.
Geordi, any progress
identifying the probe?
Maybe. I picked up
some residue on
the probe's shell.
I think it came from
the propulsion system.
Looks like they used
a solid propellant as fuel.
Solid propellant?
Sensors read this stuff
as crystalline emiristol--
produces a radioactive trail
that ought to be traceable.
Well then, we should
be able to send out
a probe of our own
to trace it back
to the origin.
I'll get right on it.
Commander,
I've been analyzing
the nucleonic beam.
I believe it would be possible
to reflect the particles
back toward the probe
in a way that would
disrupt the signal.
Doctor?
I simply don't know
the risk of shutting
down the beam.
I'm not willing to
let this thing keep
drilling into him.
If somebody gets stabbed,
you don't necessarily
pull the knife out
right away.
It might do more harm
than leaving it there.
The captain
is under attack.
We must act.
I'm inclined to agree.
Doctor,
monitor him closely.
Mr. Data, prepare
to disrupt the beam.
We're going to try
to cut this cord.
( Picard playing flute )
ELINE:
Meribor!
Meribor, this is
your brother's ceremony.
Don't fidget now.
( applause )
We name this child
for a dear friend
who died a year ago
but now his memory
will live on
in his namesake.
We name you Batai
in his honor.
And he's starting out
in the warmth of friends.
Thank you.
Please, help yourselves
to something to eat.
Congratulations,
Kamin.
Thank you.
It seems like only
yesterday we had Meribor's
naming ceremony.
Go on.
I remember.
I was so nervous,
I was afraid that
I would drop her.
Now, look at
the little lady.
Oh, she's no lady,
tromping through the
hills with you all day,
digging up those soil samples
you insist upon collecting.
No, she's
her father's daughter.
I would have believed
that I didn't need children
to complete my life.
Now I couldn't imagine
life without them.
Kamin?
What is it?
( gasping )
Get the doctor.
Hurry!
( gasping )
His respiratory
system's in spasm.
Pulse is irregular
and weakening.
I'm losing him.
I'm getting massive
somatophysical failure.
Two CCs Delactovine.
Data, get that beam back.
There are
severe fluctuations
in the isocortex.
Synaptic responses
are failing.
Begin full cardiac
induction.
Blood pressure is dropping
rapidly-- 70 over 20.
Data, you've got to
reestablish that beam.
I am attempting to
do so, Doctor.
Losing response
in the isocortex.
Cortical stimulators.
Start at ten percent.
The beam is fully
restored, doctor.
Blood pressure
up to 90 over 40...
and rising.
Isocortical functions
are stabilizing.
Vital signs
are approaching normal.
Meribor.
Happy day, Father.
Hey, that's my hobby.
Find your own.
You're the one
who taught me.
Don't complain if you
turned me into a scientist.
And what has the scientist
been up to today?
Analyzing soil samples.
There isn't
any anaerobic bacteria.
The soil is dead.
This isn't just
a very long drought,
is it, Father?
I have entries in my log
that go back ten years.
You have data preceding
that for 15 years.
You've reached
the same conclusion.
I know you have.
I haven't reached
any conclusion.
A good scientist doesn't
function by conjecture.
A good scientist functions
by hypothesizing
and then proving or
disproving that hypothesis.
That's what I did.
Hey, why don't you
spend more time with
that young man Dannick?
You're changing
the subject.
No, I'm not.
I'm just hypothesizing
that he's in love with you.
You've taught me to
pursue the truth,
no matter how painful it is.
It's too late
to back off now.
This planet is dying.
( sighs )
Perhaps I should have
filled your head with
trivial concerns.
Games and toys
and clothes.
I don't think
you mean that.
No, I don't.
( sighs )
It just... saddens me
to see you...
burdened with the knowledge
of things you can't change.
Father, I think
I should marry Dannick
sooner rather than later,
don't you?
Seize the time, Meribor.
Live now.
Make now always
the most precious time.
Now will never
come again.
I love you, Father.
His vital signs
are holding.
They've been stable
ever since the beam
was restored.
LA FORGE:
Commander Riker,
we've started to
receive telemetry from
the probe we launched.
Go ahead.
We've charted the alien
probe's radiation trail
for over one light year.
Any way to
extrapolate an origin?
Looks like a star
system in the Silarian
sector-- Kataan.
Never heard of it.
Data?
It is an unmapped system
of six planets, sir.
Any of them inhabited?
Not any longer, sir.
The star went nova.
All life in this system
was destroyed
approximately
1,000 years ago.
I put away your shoes
for you again.
Yes. Thank you, dear.
You know, I've been
looking through this
thing on and off
for over 30 years,
and I still don't see
what you and Meribor
find so fascinating.
Fine. Then maybe
you'll sit down
and have a rest
as you're supposed to.
Oh, you treat me
like some frail flower.
People have surgery
all the time.
Hmm.
( flute music playing )
He loves playing.
He's quite good at it,
don't you think?
Well, he loves doing
a lot of things.
Last week, all he wanted
to do was be a botanist--
the week before that,
a sculptor.
I wish he could find
some focus in his life.
I think he has.
Maybe you should
talk to him.
Batai?
Father?
I get the feeling
from your mother
that you have
something to tell me.
Yes.
I was waiting
for the right moment,
but that will never come.
I'm leaving school.
Leaving school?
No, you're not!
I want to concentrate
on my music.
That's what I care about.
Well, last year, all you
cared about was mathematics.
The year before that,
botany. Now...
But through it all,
there was my music.
I think you know that,
Father.
This is the life I want.
Well, we'll, um...
we'll discuss it.
Thank you, Father.
Hmm...
Even after
all these years,
you still have the ability
to surprise me.
If music is what he
wants, why should I
stand in his way?
Anyway, who knows
how much time
he'll have
to follow any dream?
Are you still planning
to talk to the
administrator tomorrow?
Mm-hmm.
There's a possibility
he'll dismiss me
from the council.
Unless, of course,
you keep quiet.
No. The evidence
is too pronounced.
I can't stay silent.
What a surprise.
Kamin, what do you
hope to accomplish?
Spreading rumors
that the planet is doomed?
There could be chaos.
The facts are here.
At least
show them to someone
who will recognize
what they mean.
I won't be a party
to your making trouble.
Well, then,
if you won't take them,
I most certainly will.
Your observations...
your findings.
Our scientists reached
those same conclusions
two years ago.
Well, what did you
expect us to do?
Make it public?
Can you imagine
the effect?
But surely the
technology must exist
to save something
of this world.
Perhaps...
perhaps some people
could be evacuated.
Evacuated where?
Our technology is limited.
We're just beginning to
launch small missiles.
A collection
of genetic samples.
Something. Anything.
You simply cannot let
this civilization die.
Enough.
There is a plan in work.
I cannot tell you
more than that.
Father!
What is it?
It's mother. Hurry.
Doctor?
Kamin, I'm sorry.
You see?
I'll go to any length
to get your attention.
You always did have a flair
for the dramatic.
Doctor, thank you.
Batai?
Leave us alone
for a moment.
I...
I need to talk
to my husband.
Did you show
the administrator
your evidence?
I didn't have to.
They already knew.
So... he won't throw you
off the council?
No.
Good.
Remember.
Put your shoes away.
I promise.
( playful cackling )
I got you, got you,
I got you.
Now I've got you.
Some children
are certainly making
a lot of noise in here.
You shouldn't be
outside so long.
It's damaging.
You know that.
I'm wearing plenty of
your skin protector.
How about you,
young man?
Do you wear your skin
protector outdoors?
You do?
Good boy.
Happy day,
everybody.
It's time to go
see the launching.
What launching?
What is he talking about?
They're sending up
a missile, Father.
We are going to watch it.
Well, I'm not going
anywhere to watch anything.
Come on, Kamie.
Hurry up, now.
Let's go see
the launching.
Breaks my heart
to look at him.
Who?
My grandson.
Breaks my heart.
He deserves a rich,
full life, and he's
not going to get one.
Please come, Father.
Why didn't I hear anything
about a launching?
( chuckling )
Did everyone know
about this except me?
I'll, uh, I'll be
all right sitting here.
You go off
with the others.
Hold onto my grandson
and watch the damned
thing go up, for all
the good it will do.
What is it
they're launching?
You know about it,
Father.
You've already seen it.
Seen it?
What are you
talking about?
I haven't seen
any missile.
BATAI:
Yes, you have, old friend.
Don't you remember?
Batai.
You saw it just
before you came here.
We hoped our probe
would encounter someone
in the future--
someone who
could be a teacher--
someone who could tell
the others about us.
Oh...
Oh, it's me.
Isn't it?
I'm the someone.
I'm the one it finds.
That's what
this launching is--
a probe that finds me
in the future.
ELINE:
Yes, my love.
Eline...
The rest of us have been
gone a thousand years.
If you remember what we were
and how we lived,
then we'll have
found life again.
Eline...
( rocket engine rumbling )
Now we live in you.
Tell them of us,
my darling.
Something's
happening.
The nucleonic beam
has ceased, Commander.
The probe has shut down.
His cerebral functions
are stabilizing.
Mr. Worf, put a tractor beam
on that probe.
I want it in Shuttle Bay 2
for examination.
Yes, Commander.
What?
Please, Captain,
don't get up too quickly.
Captain...
This is the Enterprise.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard.
How long...?
20, 25 minutes.
25 minutes?
Captain, I want you
in sick bay.
I'd like to run
a full diagnostic on you.
Dr. Crusher...
( door chiming )
Come.
Hello, sir.
Feeling better?
Yes.
Yes, thank you.
But I find that I'm...
I'm having to rediscover
that this is really my home.
We were able to open
the probe and examine it.
Apparently, whatever
had locked onto you
must have been
self-terminating.
It isn't functioning
any longer.
We found this inside.
( playing lullaby )