Captain's Log,
Stardate 45959.1.
The Enterprise has
been recalled
to Sector 001
on a priority mission.
All we've been told is that
evidence has been discovered
indicating the presence
of extraterrestrials on Earth
five centuries ago.
Work crews were down here
installing seismic regulators
when they found some
remarkable artifacts.
And it's been determined
that they date back
to the late
19th century?
Yes.
Ahh.
DATA:
The bifocal visual aid
is typical of the era.
The weapon is a .45 caliber
double-action cavalry pistol
invented by
Colt Firearms
in 1873.
Here, look
inside the watch.
PICARD:
Hmm.
What makes you think
that extraterrestrials
are related to
these discoveries?
The crew was having a problem
with the regulators.
Something inside
the cavern was
interfering with
the phase conditioners.
It turned out to be
the cavern itself.
The composition
of the rock face
has been altered by exposure
to triolic waves.
Which you're not going
to find on Earth
in either the 19th
or 24th century.
Triolic waves?
The by-product
of an energy source
employed by very
few species
because of its deleterious
effect on living tissue.
We've confirmed
that no one has been
in or out of this cavern
in centuries.
So we're left with
a 500-year-old mystery.
I'm curious,
Doctor.
There are far greater
experts on Earth
to investigate
your mystery.
Why bring the Enterprise
all the way home?
As we continued
our excavation,
we found one other thing
I haven't shown you yet.
We've tried to leave
everything as we found it.
( fabric rustles )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45960.2.
We have transported
the materials
discovered in the cavern
back to the ship for analysis.
I wish I could be
as dispassionate
about the implications
as my second officer.
DATA:
Interesting.
There is a 12%
decomposition of bitanium
in the neural
pathway links.
That suggests that
the alloys are vulnerable...
Data, how can you
look inside that--
analyze
the decomposition
without...?
Emotion, sir?
Yes.
I am simply trying to make
an objective assessment.
Data, is this yours?
I believe so, sir.
Could it be Lore?
No, sir. My brother's
positronic brain has
a Type-L phase-
discriminating amplifier.
Mine is a Type-R.
Type R?
Yes, sir.
Can you predict how long
this has been in the cavern?
Decomposition
strongly indicates
that life was terminated
approximately 500 years ago.
That would be
consistent with
the other artifacts
we recovered.
Your head is not
an artifact.
In relative terms,
perhaps not.
Nevertheless,
it seems clear that
that my life is to end
in the late 19th century.
Not if we can help it.
There is no way anyone
can prevent it, sir.
At some future date,
I will be transported
back to 19th-century Earth,
where I will die.
It has occurred.
It will occur.
LA FORGE:
Well, I can't tell you exactly
who the aliens were,
but I have found out
a few things.
The triolicized
rock face tells us
that we're probably
dealing with a species
with microcentrum
cell membranes.
Triolic waves
wouldn't harm them.
It also might mean they're
shape-shifters of some kind.
So they could have appeared
on Earth as humans.
I don't think it's anybody
we've ever run into before.
Nothing we've found matches up
with any known life-forms.
What does match up
is a cellular fossil
which might have been
along just for the ride.
A cellular fossil?
A microscopic
ciliated life-form,
not unlike a thousand other
single cell life-forms
you'd find on
any planet surface.
Except this
particular one
is LB10445,
and LB10445 is only known
to exist on one place--
Devidia Two
in the Marrab sector.
Number One,
lay in a course.
On my way.
So, do you want
to talk about it?
Are you referring
to the foreknowledge
of my death?
Yeah.
I have no particular desire
to discuss the matter.
Do you need
to talk about it?
Yeah.
Ahh. Why?
Data, this has got
to bother you a little.
On the contrary,
I find it rather comforting.
Comforting?
I have often wondered
about my own mortality
as I have seen others
around me age.
Until now, it has been
theoretically possible
that I would live
an unlimited period of time,
and although some might
find this attractive,
to me it only
reinforces the fact
that I am...
artificial.
I never knew how tough
this must be for you.
Tough?
As in difficult?
Knowing that you would
outlive all your friends.
I expected to make
new friends.
True.
And then to outlive
them as well.
Now that you know
that you might not?
It provides a sense
of completion to my future.
In a way, I am
not that different
from anyone else.
I can now look
forward to death.
I never thought of it
that way.
One might also conclude
that it brings me one step
closer to being human.
I am mortal.
PICARD:
Picard to bridge officers.
We're approaching
the Devidia system.
Report
to your stations.
I'll see you later.
Let's get together
for a game of chess
or something, okay?
That sounded like
a very intense discussion.
Yeah...
they found Data's head
a mile beneath San Francisco.
Been down there
about five centuries.
That's why the Enterprise
is being sent back to Earth.
I didn't realize.
Something, isn't it?
He seems fine about it.
Better than I am.
Well, I'd better
get to Engineering.
Full circle.
Hmm.
I heard about Data.
Yeah.
It's having an unusually
traumatic effect on everyone.
Yeah.
If you don't want to talk
about it, it's okay.
I'm fine,
I'm just...
Angry.
I'm not angry.
Yeah, I'm angry.
Why should I be angry?
Maybe because it reminds us
of our own mortality.
I just don't want
to believe it.
Have you ever heard Data
define friendship?
No.
How did he put it?
( imitating Data ):
As I experience certain
sensory input patterns,
my mental pathways
become accustomed
to them.
The inputs eventually
are anticipated
and even missed
when absent.
So what's the point?
He's used to us,
and we're used to him.
It's like finding out
someone you love
has a terminal
illness...
Data.
Counselor.
Commander.
Would either of you mind
if I made a personal inquiry?
Personal inquiry?
No, go right ahead.
I am perceiving
an apparent change
in the way others
behave toward me.
For example,
people abruptly end
conversations
when I appear,
just as you did
when the turbolift
doors opened.
Is that
an accurate observation?
Not at all--
Yes.
You're right, Data.
And it's not
a very nice thing to do.
It's just that
our mental pathways
have become
accustomed
to your sensory
input patterns.
Hmm.
I understand.
I am also fond of you,
Commander,
and you as well,
Counselor.
We're in orbit.
Any sign of life?
WORF:
Negative, sir.
Captain, sensors
are picking up
an unusual
temporal disturbance
on a small area of
the planet's surface.
42 degrees...
seven minutes north
by 88 degrees,
declination east.
Temporal
disturbance?
Put us in the standard orbit
above those coordinates.
Spectral analysis shows
a high level of triolic waves
emanating from
the same location.
Any correlation
with the readings
we received
from Earth?
Affirmative, sir.
The magnetic signature
is identical to the one
found in the cavern.
Could those triolic waves
be dangerous for humanoids?
Only with
long-term exposure, sir.
There is no
immediate threat.
Take an away team.
Worf, Geordi, Troi,
join me in
Transporter Room Three
for an away team.
Commander?
Mr. Data.
I'll need your help
to monitor the sensor readings
during this
investigation.
Captain...
may I speak
to you alone?
Sir, it is
standard procedure
that the second officer
accompany the away team.
Yes, yes, Mr. Data,
I am aware of that.
Then I must assume
your decision is related
to the discovery
on Earth...
I think
it is reasonable
to take precautions.
Captain...
there is no rational
justification for this course.
Then I'll be
irrational.
It is possible, sir,
that the events
leading to my death
will not occur for years,
even centuries.
I hope that's true,
Mr. Data.
Nevertheless,
this investigation
began with your death.
I'm simply trying to see
that it doesn't end that way.
I appreciate your
concern, Captain,
but to employ an aphorism,
one cannot "cheat fate."
Cheat fate?
( sighs deeply )
Perhaps we can't,
Mr. Data,
but at least
we can give it a try.
Hmm...
The concentration
of triolic waves
falls off about here.
Mm-hmm.
It increases exponentially
the closer in we go.
What's the source--
something underground?
Negative,
Commander.
What's the explanation?
I don't have one yet.
La Forge to Enterprise.
DATA:
Go ahead.
Data, run
a spectral field
correlation for me,
let's find out if
these triolic readings
are in any way related
to the temporal
distortions.
Acknowledged.
Deanna?
There's life here.
A child...
an old woman...
dozens more,
hundreds.
Terrified.
Terrified?
My God, Will,
they're human.
RIKER:
Whatever they are,
Troi's convinced
they're human.
They may be
trapped somehow.
We're not sure.
Captain, the results
of my temporal analysis
may be pertinent.
Go ahead.
Geordi, it indicates
a synchronic distortion
in the areas emanating
triolic waves.
Well, that explains
a few things-- how much, Data?
A positive
displacement of .004%.
Well, whatever
or whoever is there,
we're out of phase with it
but we're only talking
by a fraction
of a second.
A fraction of a second
would make them invisible?
A millisecond, a year--
it wouldn't make any difference.
If what
we're reading is true,
then we're occupying
the same space
but in a different time.
How do we
compensate?
DATA: Commander,
we might be able
to manipulate
the synchronic distortion.
LA FORGE:
Maybe, if we were
to create a contained
subspace force field.
But to get
a .004 variance,
we'd need an incredibly
sensitive
phase discriminator, Data.
I don't think
we have one that would
even come close.
Yes, we do.
It is built into
my positronic
decompiler.
It will be necessary
for me to join
the away team, sir.
Proceed, Mr. Data.
Mr. Data.
Sir.
Let me give you
a hand with that, Data.
Once I have adjusted
the force field,
I will no longer be
visible, Commander.
I have taken steps,
however, to ensure
that you will still
be able to hear me.
If you will assist me
in a test of the com system.
My voice will be
transmitted
on a delay correlated
to the phase adjustment.
That should allow me
to maintain verbal contact.
Will we be able
to talk to you?
No, sir, that will
not be possible.
The subspace field
has been established.
You're set
to go, Data.
Adjusting the synchronic
distortion.
.001...
.002.
.003...
.004.
DATA ( distorted ):
I have made visual contact.
There are
life-forms here.
They are either
unaware of me
or choosing
to ignore me.
I am moving approximately
ten meters north
of my starting position
to observe more closely.
They range from
two to three meters in height,
silver-gray
in color.
They have four limbs.
No eyes or ears are
noticeable.
There is a single orifice
where a humanoid forehead
would ordinarily be.
They are reclined
against the rock face,
surrounding an apparatus
of some sort
approximately
1.5 meters in height.
It is releasing what appear
to be energy fragments
which are then
ingested by the entities
through the orifice,
perhaps some sort
of nourishment.
The upper portion
of the apparatus
seems to be a holding facility
for the energy segments.
There are hundreds,
perhaps thousands
of these
fragments inside.
I have resumed
a northerly direction.
There is no evidence yet
of humans.
Okay, that's enough,
Data, come on back now.
I have encountered
another life-form--
an ophidian.
It seems to be restricted
by a force field.
Two of the silver-gray entities
are approaching it.
They have released
the force field.
( explosion )
I am reading
a temporal distortion...
of... mass...
...ortions...
the ophidian is...
...ime-space continuum...
...caught in
the after effect...
...I am attempting...
Data!
RIKER:
Over here.
PICARD:
Commander Riker, report.
We've lost him.
( voices murmuring )
Excuse me.
Uh, pardon me.
I am searching
for two individuals
with an ophidian.
A snake.
( laughing )
Frenchmen!
Hmm.
Could you help out
a '49er?
I-I-I fell down
a shaft.
I got blown up
in a tunnel.
That is
unfortunate.
It is most
I require large amounts
of whiskey as a liniment.
I am sorry, but I have
no whiskey to give you.
I'll take a dime.
I am sorry, but I have
no form of legal tender.
Oh. We're in
the same boat, huh?
Well, this is
my street.
You'll have to go
find one of your own.
I would be
happy to do so,
but I am presently
in search of information.
Oh.
Stockbrokers are
cheap as hell.
Don't even
bother to ask.
Your best handout
is from a young fella
with his lady.
You give him a chance
to show her he's generous.
Steer clear
of sailors.
Most likely,
you'll get a...
fist across your jaw
for your trouble.
Thank you for
your advice,
but I am
trying to find
two individuals
with a snake.
A snake?
You are an odd fellow,
aren't you?
But just don't be
too particular
where you get
your funds from.
( hacking cough )
You are in need
of medical attention.
I will get a doctor.
No, no, no.
It's too late for that.
Oh!
Could you help out
a '49er?
( sighing )
Thanks.
Hey, put it
on Gentleman Jim.
Knockout
in the fifth.
MAN:
All right.
Sir, I need
temporary lodging.
Looks like the missus
booted you out
in the middle
of the night.
Ahh, I understand the source
of your misperception.
However, this is
not sleepwear,
and I do not
have a missus.
Well...
I am a Frenchman.
Oh, well, everybody's
from somewhere.
Now, that doesn't
matter at this hotel.
It's six bits a day
or four dollars a week.
I have no money.
Well, now that matters.
But I am capable
of performing
significant tasks
both mental
and physical.
Perhaps your hotel
would offer me a job.
Geez,
I don't know.
We're pretty happy
with the maid we've got.
The cook's decent.
The dishwasher's
drunk all day--
but at least
he gets here on time--
and, uh, there's me.
I do everything else
around here.
Sorry.
Lady luck not with you
tonight, Mr. Lane?
Poor fella.
Hasn't filled a straight
in five weeks.
Poker?
Fold.
Me, too.
Go to blazes.
( chortling )
A poker face
carved in marble.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
What in hell
do you want?
I would like
to join the game.
Pale face.
Ahh, I don't like
Easterners, personally.
I am a Frenchman.
Ah, mes parents sont
originaires
de Bourgogne.
Je suis ne a la
New Orleans.
Alors, nous sommes
presque freres.
Je suis heureux
de vous connaitre.
( laughing )
Please, sir.
The game is poker.
The deal is yours.
The ante is
four bits.
Family heirloom?
In a manner
of speaking.
It is a crystalline
composite of silicon,
beryllium,
carbon 70, and...
Gold.
I'll give you
three dollars for it.
I accept.
Did you see the looks
on their faces?
I did everything
I could not to laugh.
To whom are you
referring?
Frederick La Rouque
and Joe Falling Hawk.
Those guys are
card sharks.
Sure, they, uh,
play easy at first,
not to scare off
the marks,
but, you give them
a little time,
they'll bleed a man dry.
Especially a, uh,
out-of-towner
like yourself.
What was the source
of your jocular reaction?
What was it
you found humorous?
Oh, don't you see?
They had you
pegged for a sap.
The clothes you got on,
the way you talk--
it's like you were
born yesterday.
You sure
fooled them though.
It was not my intention
to deceive.
Well, have it your way.
This is the place.
Uh, breakfast is
6:00 to 8:00.
Check-out's at noon when
you're ready to leave.
Thank you.
It has been
a pleasure.
Ahem!
It would be advisable
to monitor that cough.
I have read that
there is currently
a cholera epidemic
in San Francisco.
Never felt better.
( coughing )
Of course.
The gratuity.
Thank you for
your assistance.
A dollar?
If there's
anything you need...
it can get lonely
in San Francisco.
You might want
some company.
I can introduce you
to... Lillian.
I have no need
for companionship.
However, I do require
some supplies.
Anything you need-- I can
get it for you wholesale.
I can get it for you
less than wholesale
if you don't ask me
where it came from.
What do you need
all this stuff for?
I am an inventor.
No kidding.
Well, this stuff's
going to take awhile.
I'll have to go
clear across town.
And it's not going
to be cheap.
Will this be enough?
More than enough.
You may retain
the surplus for yourself.
Keep the change?
Exactly.
Done.
Help out a '49er...
Fell down...
a shaft.
'49er...
help me.
( wheezing )
Help me out.
No...
No!
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
Close-range sensor analysis
has yielded no further trace
of Commander Data.
Despite the emotional
repercussions among my crew,
I must move
this mission forward.
I'm not willing
to accept that he's dead
and just leave it
at that.
We cannot make
Mr. Data our priority.
What is more important
than Data?
Look at what
we have so far--
evidence that these aliens
have been traveling
in time to Earth.
What if they're
trying to undermine
our history
for some reason?
Some kind of guerrilla war?
We must assume that
there is a threat.
If not to us, then
to 19th-century Earth.
We have to determine
what that threat may be.
Mr. La Forge, we have
to find some way
to communicate
with these life-forms.
It's not going to be easy
to reproduce what Data did.
We can create
a contained subspace field,
but we'd need
an extraordinarily
sensitive phase
discriminator to get
that .004 variance.
Can you build one?
( sighs )
Won't be
as good as Data's.
Will it be good enough?
I don't know.
I can try.
It's gonna take
some time, though.
I don't want anyone else
going in alone.
I can probably
create a large enough
subspace field
to encompass everyone.
But adjusting the phase
inside the field,
that's gonna be
the hard part.
Make it so.
We have to assume
one thing, sir.
Wherever Data may be,
he's doing
the same thing we are,
which is trying to get
to the bottom of this.
He may have a better idea about
what's going on than we do.
So it might be
in the best interest
of this mission
to find him.
Perhaps in the course of
this investigation we will.
I hope so.
If we find
Commander Data,
it may be our fate to die
with him in the past.
If our remains are
in that cavern,
they would have
turned to dust long ago.
( door opens, closes )
PICARD:
I'm afraid to interrupt.
Captain...
you didn't have to come
all the way down here.
I would have been
more than happy
to have come up to you.
And miss all this?
I haven't seen such
a complex operation
since the Academy
lab final in exochemistry.
It's a Tzartak
aperitif.
It's very,
very touchy.
The trick is to change
the evaporation point
of the main ingredient.
You want the temperature
where the liquid goes to vapor
to be a half
a degree below
the body temperature
of the customer.
That way,
when the liquid
touches the tongue,
it evaporates,
and the flavor is
carried entirely
by the vapor.
A few molecules off,
the vapor point crashes,
and poof-- it's all gone.
All of it.
What is it you wanted
to see me about?
I hear you're sending
an away team
down to the surface.
Uh-huh.
Are you going?
Well, now, this is
rather unusual.
For you to be curious
about an away mission.
Maybe it's an unusual
away mission.
If you have something
to say, I'm listening.
Starfleet captains don't
usually accompany away teams.
It's general policy.
This time you have to.
Why?
You just do.
Do you remember
the first time we met?
Of course.
Don't be so sure.
I just mean...
if you don't go
on this mission...
we'll never meet.
( machinery whirring )
( thumping )
Ugh-- oh, whoo.
Sorry it took
so long, Mr. Data.
An apology is
not necessary.
Whoo.
Whoa... hey...
Ow.
Are you all right?
I believe I have
overexerted myself.
Yeah, I'll say.
Did you get it
working?
Yes.
Whatever it is.
This is for
your trouble.
What are you going
to do with the anvil?
I require a low-intensity
magnetic field core.
I believe the iron mass
of the anvil will provide that.
Well, uh,
what's it gonna be
when it's finished?
What do you think it is...
gonna be?
If I were to guess?
Maybe a, uh,
a new kind of motor
for one of those
horseless carriages.
That is a good guess.
Hot damn.
You really think there's
money in those things?
Perhaps.
Hah!
Isn't that what
makes America great?
To what are you
referring?
Well, a man rides
into town in his pajamas,
wins a grub stake
at a poker table,
turns it into
a horseless carriage,
and makes a million bucks?
That's America.
I believe I have given you
an erroneous impression.
You know, someday...
my ship's gonna come in.
You have a ship?
Oh, yeah, and it's
full of gold, too.
I'm just biding my time
till it gets here,
raising a stake
any way I can.
I've been a newsie,
cut fish at a cannery.
Heck, I've even been
an oyster pirate.
You have had a considerable
spectrum of occupations.
Yeah, well, you can't stay
in one place too long.
I'm always looking
for the angle, you know.
Say, maybe you and I could
go into business together,
selling your horseless
carriage and all.
You invent 'em,
I sell 'em.
I can sell
anybody anything.
What do you say?
I believe your plan is
a bit premature.
Well, keep it
in mind, though.
I better get back.
Oh, I forgot.
I got you something
at the bakery on Third.
Oh.
Thank you, Jack.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's on me...
partner.
MAN:
The eminent scientist
Alfred Russell Wallace
has revived
the theory
that Earth is at the center
of the stellar universe.
( genteel laughter )
This, uh...
distinguished...
natural...
philosopher...
has, uh,
reaffirmed our planet
as the only habitable globe
in the heavens.
A world, furthermore
constructed for
the sole benefit of man.
Hmm.
He's got a lot of folks
excited about the notion.
My dear,
Mr. Clemens,
why do I think you're
not one of them?
Your suspicions,
Madame Guinan,
are undoubtedly
based upon
your keen
observational skills.
( chuckles )
Now, if you'll
permit me,
I'll continue my character
assassination unimpeded.
My dear, Mr. Clemens,
please do, please do.
According to our best
geologic estimate,
the earth is approximately
100 million years of age.
Perhaps it is less,
perhaps more.
Perhaps
a great deal more.
Indeed.
But regardless,
it is ancient...
in the extreme.
Now, geology also
tells us
that man himself
has existed but for
a microscopic fraction
of those years.
( chuckling )
Curious, isn't it?
That the world got by
for such
a great long while
with no humans around
to fill up space.
I suppose
Mr. Wallace
and his supporters
would say that the Earth
needed all that time
to prepare itself
for our illustrious
arrival.
Why...
the oyster alone
probably required
15 million years
to get it to come out
just right.
( laughter )
But if the Earth is
not alone, and there are
millions of inhabited
planets in the heavens...
Quite my point.
Man becomes a trivial
creation, does he not?
Lost in the vastness
of the cosmic prairie,
adrift on the deep
ocean of time.
A single one amongst...
( chuckles )
...countless others.
Some may argue
that a diamond is
still a diamond,
even if it is one
amongst millions.
It still shines
as brightly.
Someone might say that,
dear lady,
if someone thought
that the human race was
akin to a precious jewel.
( people chuckling )
But this...
increasingly
hypothetical someone...
would not be me.
( people laughing )
Good afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon.
I would like
to speak to Guinan.
And you are?
Data.
Mr. Data.
Could it be under
another name?
No.
I can't seem
to find your name
on the guest list,
sir.
I am a personal friend.
Madame Guinan
has discovered
many personal friends
since the newspaper
announcement,
but if your name is
not on the guest list,
there's nothing
I can do.
It is urgent that
I speak to her.
Sir, unless you leave
this house immediately,
I will send
for the police.
That is
an excellent idea.
I will wait
for them in there.
Sir, please,
you can't go in there.
DATA:
Guinan!
I must speak to you
immediately.
Forgive me, madam,
he just barged right in.
I am sorry
for the disruption,
but he would not
believe me when
I told him
we were friends.
Do I know you,
Mister...?
...Data. Yes.
We were on
a ship together.
Well, I do
so much traveling.
What ship would that be?
The Enterprise.
Is that
a clipper ship?
It is a starship.
Starship?
What registry
would that be?
Of course!
Mr. Data-- oh.
Excuse us...
we have so much
to catch up on.
Excuse us.
Just... how are you?
What exactly are you?
Android.
Artificial
life-form.
Ahh...
did my father
send you here?
Because if he did,
you must go back
and tell him
I'm not done listening...
I was not sent
by your father.
Circumstances demand
that I take you
into my confidence.
I require
your assistance.
...sorry.
I am from
the 24th century,
where you and I serve
aboard a starship.
And?
Our ship encountered
a species who appears
to be threatening
19th-century Earth.
I investigated
and was inadvertently
pulled into their
temporal vortex.
Ahh...
When I saw
your photograph
in the newspaper,
I assumed you had
joined me from
the future...
From the Enterprise.
I knew your species
was long-lived,
but I did not realize
you had visited Earth
so long ago.
( clearing throat )
Eavesdropping is
by no means
a proper activity
for a gentleman.
Nonetheless...
the deed is done.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 45965.3.
An away team has beamed
to the surface
with a device
which may enable them
to phase-shift into
the alien world.
Okay, Counselor,
right over there.
The triolic waves
end right here.
Mr. Worf.
Sir.
How soon
will you be ready?
We're ready now,
Captain.
The subspace field is
established.
I'd be more comfortable
if you'd monitor our progress
from the bridge,
Captain.
I have reason to believe
that my presence
on this mission is
imperative.
RIKER:
Imperative?
Yes. Mr. Worf.
You will report
back to the bridge.
Sir...
as chief of security,
my place is at your side.
The security
of the Enterprise
is of paramount
importance, Mr. Worf.
Yes, sir.
Worf to Enterprise.
MALE VOICE:
Go ahead, sir.
Beam me up.
Proceed,
Mr. La Forge.
I've modified
this tricorder
to interface with
the subspace generator.
It should allow me to control
the phase discrimination--
assuming this is
going to work at all.
I'll need everyone
inside the field.
Adjusting synchronic
distortion...
.001.
.002.
.003.
.004...
If we can see them,
why can't they see us?
The phase displacement
might not bring us
far enough into
their perceptual range.
These strands appear
to be biomagnetic,
variable flux, possibly
organic in origin.
A life-form.
No.
There's no life here.
What I have sensed is...
more like
an imprint...
an echo of the last
moment of life.
Human life.
They all died
in terror.
My God.
They're delivering more of them
for the others to ingest.
Look at what
he's carrying.
( snarling )