Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
They found Data's head
a mile beneath San Francisco.
Been down there
about five centuries.
At some future date
I will be transported back
to 19th-century Earth,
where I will die.
It has occurred.
It will occur.
Do I know you, Mr...
Data.
Yes. We were on
a ship together.
The Enterprise.
Is that a clipper ship?
It is a starship.
Starship?
RIKER:
My God.
They're delivering more of them
for the others to ingest.
Did my father
send you here?
Because if he did,
you must go back
and tell him I'm not
done listening...
I was not sent
by your father.
Our ship encountered
a species
who appears to be threatening
19th-century Earth.
I'm not willing to accept
that he's dead
and just leave it at that.
We cannot make
Mr. Data our priority.
What is more
important than Data?
Do you remember
the first time we met?
Of course.
Don't be so sure.
If you don't go
on this mission,
we'll never meet.
And now, the conclusion.
SAMUEL CLEMENS:
I've long been interested
in the notion of time travelers.
In fact, I wrote a book
about it.
It chronicles the tale
of a man of our era
who fouls the sixth century by
introducing newfangled gadgets
and weapons, all in
the name of progress.
But, uh...
( spits )
But this, uh, idea
of time travel--
not so farfetched
as it might seem.
In fact, I have just
learned that even now
there are people
from the future
right here in San Francisco,
and I have no doubt that their
intent is to foul our world
just like my Yankee did
in King Arthur's time.
Well, sir, let me
serve notice.
As soon as I have
the necessary evidence
I intend to expose them
and make it absolutely clear
that they are not welcome here.
Yes, sir,
and will this be a sequel
to Connecticut Yankee,
Mr. Twain?
Name is Clemens, boy.
Sam Clemens.
That's with an "E."
With an "E."
Got it.
Excuse me.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
RIKER:
The coroner said
this is where they kept
all the cholera victims.
It doesn't make sense
that so many people
are dying of cholera.
It just isn't that virulent.
( tricorder beeping )
Will.
This is strange.
What is it?
The cerebellum,
the cerebral cortex,
the brain stem,
the entire nervous system
has been depleted
of electrochemical energy.
Here's another one.
Same neural depletion.
These people
did not die of cholera.
They died because their neural
energy was drained somehow.
Drained?
And taken to Devidia II
for those aliens to ingest?
If you were a time traveler
with a taste
for human neural energy,
where would you get
your supply?
I would travel
back to a time
when there were plagues
and epidemics,
so I could murder and use
the disease as a cover.
Over half of the victims
whose neural energy
have been drained
came from
the Sisters of Hope Infirmary.
RIKER: The charity hospital
near the waterfront.
If the aliens have been
killing people there,
well, someone might have
noticed something unusual.
And if they're moving
among humans,
then they must have taken on
human form.
But the question is how do we
know who we're looking for?
The tricorder indicated
triolic activity
from most of the bodies
we've looked at.
If the aliens left
that sort of signature,
they'll be detectable.
You know, we might
even be able
to rig some kind
of alien alarm system.
Any luck contacting Data?
None. Tricorder's broadcasting
random emissions
on all frequencies
his subprocessors might pick up,
but the range is limited.
Almost anything
could interfere.
( knocking )
She's back.
MRS. CARMICHAEL:
Mr. Picard?
( knocking )
Yes, Mrs. Carmichael?
Mr. Picard,
I'll be reminding you
that it's 1:00.
Yes.
1:00 on a Thursday.
I'm sure I made
it clear to you
that the rent is always
due, payable in full,
by 1:00 on Wednesdays.
Ah, yes.
Uh... the rent.
Uh, Mrs. Carmichael...
even now, my, uh...
my troupe are in rehearsals
for a new production.
Oh?
I haven't heard
of any new production.
What play is it?
The play.
A Midsummer Night's Dream.
We have performed
in London, Paris,
Milan...
Milan, to sold out houses.
I can assure you
you will have the rent in full,
with a bonus.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I've heard you
silver-tongued
devils before.
I'll have my rent
in full tomorrow by 1:00
or you'll be out
performing on the street.
( door closes )
I wouldn't do this for
just anyone, Mr. Clemens,
and I hope you won't spread
it around that I let you in.
You know, people
start talking.
Of course not, Jack.
And I assure you
that Mr. Data
would be most upset
if you didn't.
If I can't find
that letter of intent
that he left me,
our major investor
is going to pull out
and take his business
elsewhere.
It has to do
with Mr. Data's
engine, doesn't it?
Engine?
Well, yes.
Oh, yes...
Yes...
This is exactly
what it's all about.
Ow!
You know, Mr. Clemens,
I'm going to do you
another favor today.
You're always looking
for good stories, right?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I've got
a real humdinger for you.
The, uh, story of my life.
Now, I know you
may think I'm young,
but I've covered
a lot of ground
and, if I do say so myself
it'd make for some pretty
fascinating reading.
So, uh, what do you think?
About what?
About writing my life story.
You and me--
literary partners,
of course.
Young man, I have a maxim
that I have always lived by.
No one is more qualified
to write your story
than you are.
Me, be a writer?
You think I
could do that?
Long as you write
about what you know.
You got any passions, boy?
Any dreams?
Well, I'd like to do
some traveling,
maybe go to sea.
And Alaska.
I've had the strangest notion
to go see Alaska.
That's a great idea, son!
That's exactly
what I would do
if I were your age.
Alaska, the Klondike,
the Aurora Borealis...
That's it!
Follow your dreams,
and write about them.
Thank you, Mr. Clemens.
You know, that is exactly
what I'm going to do.
You do that, son.
You'll see my name
in print, too.
I'm sure I will.
And don't forget-- the name's
London. Jack London.
Good-bye, now.
Bye-bye.
( sighs deeply )
( outside door closes )
( footsteps and voices
approaching )
I found the head surveyor.
I found the cavern.
You will not be able
to get to it.
The entrance
is on a mine shaft
that is in the middle
of the Presidio
on an army base.
Perhaps you could arrange
for us to get in.
( scoffs ):
How?
With permission to dig
for the mine shaft.
Oh, now, Data,
I've done everything...
I have full confidence
in your persuasive
abilities.
Well, I suppose
it's more interesting
than throwing a tea dance.
Strange--
the transceiver assembly
has been removed.
Without it, I will be unable
to track the time shifts.
Twain.
Clemens?
Yes.
He's been driving me crazy.
He watches the house.
He follows me down the street
asking me questions.
If anyone took this,
you can believe it was him.
If you are correct,
he must be warned.
The device has been
modified in such a way
that prolonged contact
with human tissue
would be highly toxic.
( clattering )
( sheepish grunt )
Madam Guinan, Mr. Data.
Shame on you,
Mr. Clemens. Shame.
Shame, madam?
I think not.
I find no shame in my efforts
to uncover your plot!
I keep telling you
there is no plot.
Yes, you do keep
telling me that.
What an interesting pair
you are.
Where in Switzerland
did you say you
were from. Mr. Data?
I am French, sir,
not Swiss.
Oh, yes, that's right.
Now, I remember.
A Frenchman
with a talent for poker,
from what I hear.
You know, I was talking
to a friend of mine,
Ches Whitley.
He says to say hello
and wonders
when you're coming back.
I do not believe
I know a Mr. Whitley.
No? He works in
the county assayer's office.
He says you've been in there
a number of times
claiming to be
a geological engineer
and wanting information
about mining operations
during the 1850s.
You remember him now?
I am unfamiliar
with the gentleman's name.
I have spoken to several
people in that office.
Yes, I know,
and in the Hall of Records
and in the Geological Society
and in a little-known
mineral shop in Chinatown.
You do get around,
don't you?
As apparently you do,
Mr. Clemens.
Yes. I must admit
you've got me mystified.
This contraption,
for instance.
It's very unusual.
It looks quite futuristic.
Tell me, might it
have something to do
with "time shifts"?
In a sense.
The time shift is
a gearing system
I have invented
for the horseless
carriage.
Ah! Do not
insult me!
You have come here
to this century
and brought your infernal
technologies with you
for God only knows
what purpose,
but I have no doubt
it will be the people
of this century
who will suffer for it.
My dear Mr. Clemens,
I do think we've heard enough.
Mr. Data's business
is his own
and I will thank you
to leave now.
Pardon me,
Madam Guinan,
but it is my business,
too.
It is the business
of all humanity, I believe,
to stop both of you
from whatever it is
you are doing here,
and that is
what I intend to do.
( door slams )
Just what are you doing
with those lamps?
Replacing the burners.
City ordinance.
Makes it safer
in case of earthquake.
There hasn't been
an earthquake here
in 30 years.
Well, that takes care
of this ward.
Time to be moving on.
Earthquakes.
Nurse, if you can
handle things here,
I've got a meeting
with the board of patrons.
I'll try to manage.
( patients coughing )
LA FORGE:
There, by that bed,
I can see an afterimage
of triolic waves.
They've been here recently.
I'd say within
the last 24 hours.
That's the bed where
the man died last night.
This man was
complaining
about a strange
doctor and nurse
who visited
that patient.
Perhaps they're still
in the hospital.
( man coughing )
Here.
This'll make you
more comfortable.
( beeping quietly )
( tricorder alarm sounding )
Do you need any
help, Doctor?
Dr. Apollinaire felt
he had entered the algid state.
He was cyanotic,
pulse unobservable.
That's an interesting cane.
Doctor!
Hey!
( electrical crackling )
MAN:
Stand aside, stand aside.
Let me in there.
People said there
was gunfire in here.
What's going on?
Just a little
misunderstanding.
I was just clearing
these people out of here.
I haven't
seen you before.
I was just assigned
here this morning.
I was working downtown.
I worked downtown
for three years.
I don't remember you.
PICARD:
We'll be on our way.
No, wait, wait--
I'm going to ask you all
to come down to the
station for questioning,
including you.
Where'd you
get that?
That's
a gentleman's cane.
I've never seen
a cane like this.
I'll have to confiscate
it for evidence.
I just want you to know
that I have the utmost
respect for the law.
Let's go!
Data!
LA FORGE:
Boy, are we glad
to see you.
I suggest we postpone
our greetings
for another occasion.
Agreed.
Get us out of here.
( whistles blowing loudly )
If we tune a phaser
to the approximate frequency
of triolic waves
and lay down a field burst,
it might respond.
Mm-hmm.
TROI:
The ophidian the aliens
were carrying.
What the...
LA FORGE:
Those look like
minute distortions
in the space-time continuum
like the one we saw
on Devidia II.
But they were so small and
they lasted only a second.
The aliens appear to be
able to concentrate
the distortion
and direct it to
a specific time and place.
Maybe they have something--
a mechanism that focuses it.
Any device like that
would produce significant levels
of triolic waves,
like the ones in the cavern
where Data's head was found.
I have located
that cavern.
( knock on door )
MRS. CARMICHAEL:
Mr. Picard!
I know you're in there.
Open the door!
TROI:
Mrs. Carmichael.
"How now, spirit.
Whither wander you?"
"Over hill, over dale,
through bush,
through brier..."
Mrs. Carmichael,
thank goodness you're here.
We need someone
to read a part.
You're just in time.
Mr. Picard, I need
to be talking to you.
CRUSHER:
"...my mistress would
that he be gone."
"Ill-met by moonlight,
proud Titania."
Now, Mrs. Carmichael,
right there.
RIKER:
"Ill-met by moonlight,
proud Titania."
( woodenly ):
"What, jealous Oberon?
"Fairies skip hence.
I have foresworn
his bed and company."
Well, I don't think
I need to hear anymore.
That was truly unique.
Really?
Ladies and gentlemen,
I think we have found
our Titania.
Don't you agree?
MRS. CARMICHAEL:
Well, I...
I did do a church play
when I was a lass.
Well, there you are!
We start rehearsals
tomorrow.
Ohh...
( door opening )
You're back.
I have wonderful news.
I've found a way to get
onto the Presidio
and into the mine shaft.
DATA:
It is all right.
Do you know me?
Very well.
Do I know you?
Not yet, but you will.
Thanks for your help,
Officer.
Now be sure to
put in the part
about me spotting
that phony policeman.
Yes, sir, I will.
Hello, son.
Mr. Clemens, what
brings you here?
Writer's curiosity.
I heard that
two people vanished
into thin air
in this infirmary.
One of the patients
said that, yes, sir
but the police deny it.
I'll bet they do.
They say a band
of outlaws
set off an explosion
in the hospital
and then escaped.
Well, what did these
outlaws look like?
The carriage they escaped
in was driven by an albino.
Oh, Mr. Data.
You know him?
Oh, you bet I do.
You say there were
others with him?
Yes, at least a dozen.
His accomplices.
They've come from the future.
My God, it's an invasion.
( whistling )
An invasion
from the future?
Mr. Clemens, what can
you tell me about this?
Do you have any proof?
When's your deadline, boy?
5:00, sir.
Well, I'll meet you
at your paper at 4:30
with a story that'll
make your career.
Thanks, Mr. Clemens!
Take me to
the Presidio, driver,
and don't spare the whip!
DRIVER:
Hyah! Hyah!
The triolic waves
are just as high
as they were on Devidia II,
but there's no indication
of a control mechanism.
I'm not so sure.
My visor is picking up
crystalline fractures.
These cavern walls
have undergone
some kind of selective
molecular polarization.
In fact, if I'm right,
this entire cavern
has been configured
to focus the space-time
distortion...
just like a lens.
Captain.
We think we might be
onto something.
The cavern itself seems to be
acting as a focusing mechanism.
I'm willing to bet that it's
the same at their habitat
back on Devidia II.
If we can get back there
and destroy that site,
it might put an end
to their time traveling.
We have the ophidian.
Truthfully, I don't know
that we can get back.
The aliens use triolic energy
as a power source.
The energy that
our phasers generates
might not be
entirely compatible.
We have no choice
but to try.
CLEMENS:
An event I most certainly
would enjoy witnessing.
However...
I will regretfully
waive that opportunity
for the privilege
of taking you all
in to the authorities.
Mr. Clemens, it is imperative
that we continue our mission.
Mr. Data, I have listened to
your stories and your excuses
and your evasions,
and I will listen no longer!
It is my moral duty
to protect mankind
from whatever devious plan
you have in mind.
Now, move along.
I suspect that
even time travelers
are vulnerable
to the Colt .45.
Now, let's go.
I made a young fellow
a promise,
and I don't
want to be late.
Uhh!
( electrical crackling )
( explosion )
Follow him.
Ow.
Is everyone all right?
I think so.
You?
Where are we?
And when?
This is the 24th century,
we're on Devidia II,
and you're not supposed
to be here.
Well, it seems to me
I have as much right
to be in your time
as you had to be in mine.
I wanted to see how you've
conducted my future affairs.
Your future
affairs?
The affairs
of mankind.
But the disappearance
of Mark Twain--
one of the most noted
literary figures
of the 19th century...
Thank you.
...that's not supposed
to happen.
I only took advantage of
an irresistible opportunity,
as any good writer would.
WORF:
Bridge to away team.
Acknowledge.
We're here, Mr. Worf.
Stand by to transport five.
LA FORGE:
Commander?
Mr. Worf.
WORF: Yes, Commander.
Make that six
to transport.
Where are we now?
This is the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
Ensign, call security.
I want an escort
for this man.
Security?! What for?
Are you afraid I'm going
to go around stealing things?
A werewolf!
It's a long story, Mr. Worf.
I'll brief you later.
LA FORGE:
Let's have Data's body
taken to the science lab.
I'm going to try and
reattach the head we have.
Geordi, that head
is over 500 years old.
Yeah, but it's the
best chance we've got.
I want Mr. Clemens kept
under escort at all times.
TROI:
Commander,
perhaps I could handle that.
I'd be happy to take
Mr. Clemens to his quarters.
Good idea.
Will you accompany
the counselor?
Madam, I'd be delighted.
So, this is a spaceship.
You ever run into
Halley's comet?
( moans )
Gently.
( groaning )
Now, don't sit up
too quickly.
( groaning )
Where'd everybody go?
Well, I hope they're
all safely back
on the Enterprise
by now.
But you're still here.
You were hurt.
I had to make sure
you were all right.
And so you stayed for that?
I didn't want anything
to happen to you.
You're far too
important to me.
You know an awful lot
about me.
Well... believe me,
in the future,
the tables
will be turned.
Do we become friends?
Oh...
it goes far beyond
friendship.
Oh, but...
I'll have to wait
500 years...
Mm-hmm.
And when we meet,
I won't even be able
to tell you about this,
will I?
No, because, for me,
none of this will
have happened yet.
( groans )
Ohh...
What's that?
That's history
fulfilling itself.
Oh.
( quiet conversations )
History has
to fulfill itself.
Even Picard knew that.
You were there
in the cavern.
You know what happened.
What am I
supposed to do?
If I told you what happened
in that cavern,
it might affect
any decision you'd make now.
I can't do that.
I won't.
Not telling me may
affect my decision.
Did you think of that?
We're talking
about Jean-Luc Picard.
I can't sit around
and hope it all works out.
I've got to do something!
Any place that
doesn't stock
a good cigar
doesn't rank high
in my book.
If you must have one,
I'm sure we can
replicate it for you.
Oh, if you think
that one of these...
imitations can take the place
of a hand-wrapped Havana...
I wouldn't know.
Well, that's
the problem I see here.
All this technology
only serves to take away
life's simple pleasures.
You don't even let a man
open the door for a lady.
I think
what we've gained
far outweighs anything
that might have been lost.
Oh?
Well, I'm not so impressed
with this future--
huge starships and weapons
that can no doubt
destroy entire cities.
Military conquest
as a way of life?
Is that what you see here?
Well, I know
what you say--
that this is a vessel
of exploration
and that your mission is to
discover new worlds, but...
( chuckles )
but that's what
the Spanish said.
Deck 36.
And the Dutch
and the Portuguese.
It's what all conquerors say.
I'm sure that's what
you told that... that...
blue-skinned fellow I just saw
before you brought him here
to serve you.
He's one of the
thousands of species
that we've encountered.
We live in a peaceful
federation with most of them.
The people you see
are here by choice.
So, there are a privileged few
who serve on these ships
living in luxury
and wanting for nothing,
but what about
everybody else?
What about the poor?
You ignore them.
Poverty was eliminated
on Earth a long time ago
and a lot of other things
disappeared with it--
hopelessness,
despair, cruelty...
Young lady,
I come from a time
when men achieve
power and wealth
by standing on the backs
of the poor,
where prejudice
and intolerance are commonplace
and power is an end
unto itself,
and you're telling me
that isn't how it is anymore?
That's right.
Hmm.
Hmm...
Maybe...
it's worth giving up
cigars for after all.
( door opens )
Any luck?
Not so far.
His activating units
won't initialize.
I thought they would
have been protected
by his buffering program,
but... I guess 500 years
is just too long a wait.
What...?
My watch!
( chuckles )
Yeah.
It was found in the cavern
where Data's head was.
I guess after 500 years,
that's not likely
to work, either.
Mr. Data...
I fear I have sadly
misjudged you...
as I have misjudged
many things.
( moaning )
Can you communicate?
Mm.
Yes.
You're injured.
Why have you
interfered with us?
You hunt us.
You kill us.
We cannot allow that.
We need your energy.
Well, perhaps we can
find a substitute.
No.
There is none.
We must continue.
We know how you move
back and forth through time.
My crew have returned
to the 24th century
to destroy your transport site
on Devidia II.
Destroy it?
Your weapons will only
amplify the time distortion.
You will annihilate
your own world.
I'm going back
for Captain Picard.
Mr. Worf, assemble an away team
to accompany me to the surface.
Doctor, I need to know
anything you can tell me
about that Ophidian.
I've just started
running some tests.
If I can have
a few hours...
I can't give the alien
any more time.
Will, I haven't
been able to determine
if our phaser energy
can generate a stable field.
The risk would be...
I'll take that risk!
Sir, permission
to speak frankly.
RIKER:
Go ahead.
Our priority is
to stop the aliens
from any more incursions
to Earth.
Any delay is
unacceptable.
If I can save Captain Picard,
I consider that very acceptable.
The captain would not.
I recommend we target
photon torpedoes
on the alien habitat
and destroy it... immediately.
He's right, Will.
Power up the photons, Mr. Worf.
Alert me when they're ready.
Computer... initialize
the reload circuits.
COMPUTER:
Reload circuits
are initializing.
Okay.
Data... this ought to do it.
Oh, I don't get it.
I don't understand why
this isn't working.
( sighs )
Computer...
run me a diagnostic
on the input polarizers.
There is intermittent
contact in the input polarizers.
Intermittent?
What...?
An iron filing.
How'd that get in there?
( sighs )
Commander, I have
set the photons
to fire in
staggered rounds
detonating in
ten-second intervals.
Very well.
Fire when ready.
The sequence will be ready
to initiate in one minute.
Computer, run another diagnostic
on the input polarizers.
COMPUTER: Polarizer circuits
are functioning.
Well, then,
that ought to do it.
( chuckles )
Okay, Data, come on now.
Torpedoes...
phasing...
alien...
( clicks )
I am processing
a binary message
entered into my static
memory by Captain Picard.
Geordi, are we
planning to fire
on the alien habitat?
Yeah, but...
It is imperative
that we do not.
I will explain later.
La Forge to Riker.
Hold your fire!
The binary message
left by the Captain
is not entirely clear.
He seemed to be concerned
about the phase differential
of our photon torpedoes.
That firing them might produce
catastrophic effects.
Then how
can we destroy
their habitat?
If I am correct,
we must modify our weapons so
that the force of the explosion
is rephased into
the aliens' time continuum.
If we outfit the photons
with phase discriminators
we could get
the variance we need.
How long
will it take you?
At least a couple of hours.
Fine. I'll have time
to go get him.
Sir?
I'm going back
to the 19th century
to get the captain.
Doctor?
My analysis of the phasers
suggests you'd be able
to open the rift,
but it won't be stable enough
to transport
more than one person.
You mean, if I go back,
only one of us could return?
CRUSHER:
That's right.
Then I have
the perfect solution for you.
I'm the one who should return
to the 19th century
and remain there, so your
captain can return here.
There's a risk.
We're not sure how stable
the rift will be.
Ah, there's risk
in everything.
The point is,
it's the right choice.
I've got more books
to write
and your captain
has a job to do here.
Geordi, you'll brief him
on what he needs to know?
Aye, sir.
I'm glad I have a chance
to thank you.
For what, sir?
Why, for starting me out
on the greatest adventure
a man's ever had, whoo!
And for helping
a bitter old man
to open his eyes
and see that the future
turned out pretty well...
after all.
I'm thirsty.
I'm going
to get help.
We have to get you
out of here.
Oh, no, don't go.
They'll be back
for you soon.
No. You need help.
( approaching footsteps )
This thing put me down
in the middle of Market Street.
Took forever to get here.
Commander La Forge
has just completed
the reconfiguration
of the photon torpedoes.
If Clemens got back,
the captain should
have been here by now.
We have no way
of knowing
if Mr. Clemens
was successful.
Reestablish your
firing pattern, Mr. Worf.
We'll wait five more minutes.
Aye, sir.
There's no time
for chitchat, sir.
According to Mr. La Forge--
who did get your message,
by the way--
a frequency setting of, uh...
.047 on your phaser
will correctly activate
this... this creature.
Now you have
to get help.
Guinan needs
medical attention.
I promise you, she
will be attended to.
And there is a bill
to be settled
at Mrs. Carmichael's
boarding house.
I'll settle it.
Thank you.
I wish...
I wish time would
have allowed me
to know you better.
Well, you'll just have
to read my books.
What I am
is pretty much there.
I'll see you
in 500 years, Picard.
And I'll see you
in a few minutes.
Commander, I am picking up
massive triolic wave activity
on the surface.
Is it the captain?
There are no
human life signs.
No sign of temporal
distortion?
No, sir, but triolic
activity is increasing.
The aliens.
Mr. Worf,
are the photons ready?
Yes, sir.
Fire.
Torpedoes away, sir.
Sir, I am detecting a temporal
distortion on the surface...
and human life signs.
( explosions )
O'Brien, get him
out of there!
Transporter room,
have you got him?
PICARD:
He has indeed, Commander,
and believe me,
it's good to be back.
WORF:
We have destroyed
the target.
There is no further indication
of triolic activity.
Ensign, lay in a course
for the nearest starbase.
Warp six.
Captain's log,
Stardate 46001.3.
Everyone who should be in the
19th century is safely there,
and those who should be
in the 24th are here.
Mr. Data has been restored
to us, head and all,
and Samuel Clemens
will write the books
he was to have written
after our encounter.
Now, be careful, boys.
Don't jostle her too much.
Don't worry, Madam Guinan,
you're going to be fine.
( chuckles )