Captain's Log,
Stardate 46041.1:
We have located
the USS Yosemite,
a Starfleet science vessel
sent to the Igo sector
to observe
a remote plasma streamer.
The ship has not been
heard from in several days.
Magnify.
The last report we have
says they were observing
the streamer
at medium range.
Maybe they went in
for a closer look...
got more than
they bargained for.
Hail them.
No response.
Life signs?
Our scanners
cannot penetrate
the plasma streamer's
distortion field.
Can we tractor them out?
No, sir, ionic interference
is too heavy.
I'll take a shuttle in.
Too risky.
You could be
pulled in, too.
Bridge to Engineering.
Mr. La Forge, can we beam an
away team onto the science ship?
We can beam them
over there, Captain,
but with all this
interference,
we might not get a positive
lock to bring them back.
Commander, if we bridged our
transporter system with theirs,
we might be able to
cut through the ionic field.
That's a good idea, Barclay.
Captain,
I think we can do it.
We're going to bridge
the two transporter systems.
PICARD: Acknowledged.
Meet Commander Riker in
Transporter Room three.
Aye, sir.
Barclay, I'm going to need
a systems engineer
on this away team.
I'll... I'll ask
Ensign Dern to join you.
I meant you, Barclay.
Shouldn't I stay here
and set up the remote link?
Dern can do that.
Come on, let's go.
Status, Mr. O'Brien?
I'll have to send you over
one at a time, Commander,
because of
bandwidth limitations.
And the transport cycle
will take a bit longer.
RIKER: How much longer?
O'BRIEN: Four or five seconds--
about twice
the normal time.
I'm afraid you're in
for a bumpy ride, Commander.
What do you...
What exactly do you mean
by "a bumpy ride"?
Well, there may be
a small amount
of static charge
accumulation.
You'll feel a bit
of tingling.
It's nothing
to worry about.
Let's do it.
Mr. Worf.
O'BRIEN:
Engaging system interlock.
Pattern buffers
synchronized.
Phase transition coils
at standby.
Energizing.
He's there.
I'll go next.
O'BRIEN:
Engaging interlock.
Buffers synched.
Energizing.
I'm ready.
O'BRIEN:
Engaging interlock.
Buffers in sync.
Oh, wait a minute.
I'm reading an ionic fluctuation
in the matter stream.
Oh. No problem.
Okay. Energizing.
( breathing slowly
and heavily )
Reg, you're up.
Reg?
Aye, sir.
O'BRIEN:
Engaging interlock.
Buffers in sync.
Phase coils...
I'm sorry.
I just can't do this.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Reg, you were faced
with a difficult transport.
Anyone would have been
apprehensive in that situation.
You tell that
to Commander La Forge
and the rest of
the away team.
I'm sure
they understand.
As soon as you
feel up to it,
you can probably
still join them.
No!
Reg, is there something
you're not telling me?
Actually...
it's, this is not the...
this is not the first time
I've been apprehensive.
Every single time
that I tried to do it,
I had this certain feeling,
and I guess...
you could call it...
mortal terror.
Why have you kept it a secret?
Why?!
Because my career in Starfleet
would be over, that's why.
I doubt that.
I've always managed
to avoid it somehow.
You wouldn't believe
how many hours
that I've logged in
shuttlecraft.
I mean, the idea
of being deconstructed
molecule by molecule--
it's more than I can stand.
Even when I was a child,
I always had a dreadful fear
that if ever
I was dematerialized,
that I would...
never come back again whole.
I know it sounds crazy, but...
It's not crazy at all.
You are being taken apart
molecule by molecule.
Reg, you're not
the first person
to have anxiety
about transporting.
We can desensitize you
to this type of fear.
It's a slow and gradual
process, but it works.
It does? How?
Well,
you might first try
a relaxation technique,
like plexing.
Plexing?
Yes, it's
a Betazoid method.
The next time you feel
nervous about transporting,
you stimulate a neural
pressure point, like this.
There's a nerve cluster
just behind the carotid artery.
It stimulates
the part of the brain
that releases
natural endorphins.
Plexing...
sounds easy enough.
Here. There.
Hmm.
You know, I... I...
I feel better already.
I think I can do this.
There's no need to rush.
No, no, no.
We talked about
confronting my fears.
"The best way out is through."
You said that once, remember?
I suppose I did.
I'm going to beam over there.
I can do it.
There's no sign
of any survivors.
No sign of anyone.
Maybe they abandoned ship.
WORF:
Unlikely.
The escape pods
are still on board.
There was an explosion here.
That much we do know.
Any idea what caused it?
I ruled out
a reactor core failure
and there's no sign
of a systems overload.
Blast analysis indicates
the explosion originated here,
in the center
of the transport chamber.
How is that possible?
The transporter
is still functional.
Could they have
beamed aboard
an explosive device?
Commander Riker?
Could you come here, please?
Excuse me.
Lieutenant Joshua Kelly.
He was the ship's engineer.
How did he die?
He has second- and third-degree
burns over most of his body,
but I don't think they were
the cause of his death.
I'd like to take him back
to do an autopsy.
You're sure
about this, sir?
Sure.
Please proceed.
It'll only take a minute.
Oh, it should be
a smooth ride over.
Good. Good.
I know how you feel
about this, sir.
You're... you're afraid
of transporting, too?
No. Arachnids.
Sickening, crawly little
things, don't you think?
All those legs...
Spiders...
they've never bothered me.
A few years back,
I was called in
to reroute an emitter array
at a starbase at Zayra IV.
Turns out the entire system
was infested
with Talarian hook spiders.
You ever seen
a Talarian hook spider?
Their legs
are half a meter long.
Well, I had a choice.
Do I walk away and let
the emitter blow itself to hell
or do I crawl in the Jefferies
tube with 20 hook spiders?
Wh... what happened?
It was the hardest thing
I ever did,
but I got through it.
After that, I was never
quite so afraid of spiders.
Thanks.
Energizing.
Reg.
Welcome aboard.
You ready to work?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Why don't you start
by downloading
the ship's science logs
over there.
Aye, sir.
Still four members of
the crew unaccounted for.
Did you come up
with anything?
Well, I don't know
how these fit in,
but I found them all around
the transporter platform.
What are they?
They look like pieces of
a standard sample container.
We'll take these back to
the ship and analyze them there.
Mr. Barclay?
Glad you could join us.
Me, too, sir.
The Ferengi are claiming
two of their freighters
were destroyed by a Cardassian
warship in your sector.
Is there any evidence
to support this?
Although I'm loath to believe
the Ferengi about anything,
there was evidence
of Cardassian weapons.
If the Cardassians
also attacked the Yosemite,
it could indicate a large-scale
movement in this sector.
I have an away team
on board the ship.
The initial report indicates
there was an explosion on board,
but we're not sure
if it was from an attack.
How soon until you know?
A few hours.
If it looks like Cardassians,
I'll contact you immediately.
Very well.
DATA:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Mr. Data.
The away team is returning
to the Enterprise, sir.
Acknowledged.
Have Commander Riker
come to my Ready Room
as soon as he's on board.
Aye, sir.
La Forge to
Transporter Room three.
I'm ready to go.
Stand by, Commander.
Barclay to Enterprise.
One to beam back.
O'BRIEN:
Stand by, sir.
See, sir?
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Mission logs, science logs,
medical logs--
they're all scrambled.
Looks like the blast wiped out
the ship's core memory.
We could try
to reconstitute
the data stream.
It's worth a try.
Commander,
has anything strange
ever happened to you
during transport?
Like what?
I don't know.
Anything out of
the ordinary?
No, not really.
This looks hopeless.
We're not going to get
anything out of these logs.
You know, maybe...
this broken sample container
I found can tell us something.
Let's try to get this thing
back into one piece.
I mean... have...
ha-have you ever
seen anything?
Where?
In the...
during transport.
Sometimes my visor
picks up resonance patterns
from matter-energy
conversion.
It's actually
kind of pretty.
Why?
I'm just wondering.
Reg, what are you getting at?
Did you see something
during transport?
When I was returning
to the Enterprise,
I could have sworn I saw
something in the matter stream.
Something?
There was phased matter
all around
and, at first,
I thought it was some kind of,
uh, energy discharge,
but then, it flew toward me
and touched my arm.
How could something
be in there?
Molecules flying apart
half-phased--
I mean...
it's impossible, isn't it?
Well, we'd better
check it out.
When we're done here,
we'll run a full diagnostic
on the transporter, all right?
All right.
The confinement beam
subsystems check out,
so do the phase
transition coils.
The pattern buffer is fine.
Emitter pads,
targeting scanners...
they're all working fine.
This system's clean
and so is
the science vessel's.
Reg, there's a lot of energy
floating around in the beam.
Maybe you saw a surge
in the matter stream.
Yeah.
I'll run a scan on
the Heisenberg compensators.
Oh, no, Chief,
you've done enough already.
It's no problem.
Why don't you
give me a hand?
You know, maybe ignorance
really is bliss.
Sir?
Well, if I didn't know
so much about these things,
maybe they wouldn't
scare me so much.
I can still remember the day
in Dr. Olafson's
Transporter Theory class
when he was talking
about the body
being converted into billions
of kiloquads of data...
zipping through subspace,
and I realized
there's no margin for error.
One atom out of place and...
poof!
You never come back.
It's amazing people
aren't lost all the time.
With all due respect, sir,
I've been doing this
for 22 years
and I haven't lost
anybody yet.
Yes, but...
you realize if the imaging
scanners are off
even one-thousandth
of a percent...
That's why each pad
has four redundant scanners.
If any one scanner fails,
the other three take over.
Reg, how many
transporter accidents
have there been
in the last ten years?
Two? Three?
There are millions of people
who transport safely every day
without a problem.
I've heard of problems.
What about
transporter psychosis?
Transporter psychosis?!
There hasn't been a case of
that in over 50 years--
not since they perfected
the multiplex pattern buffers.
Reg, transporting really is
the safest way to travel.
( sighs )
I'd like to take
a closer look at those burns.
Take a tissue sample, please.
Yes, Doctor.
Damage to the epidermis only.
Initiate a circulatory probe.
( beeping )
Dr. Crusher!
His heart's beating.
Cardio-stimulator.
Now.
OGAWA:
It's gone.
Neuro-electrical activity
in the cerebral cortex.
Nothing.
Now his respiratory
system's active.
What the hell is going on?
Here you are,
Lieutenant.
Water-- ten degrees Celsius.
Computer, access
Starfleet Medical Database
and tell me about, um...
describe the disorder
"transporter psychosis."
COMPUTER: Transporter psychosis
was diagnosed in the year 2209
by researchers
on Delinia II...
No, no, stop.
All I need is...
what causes it?
COMPUTER:
It is caused by a breakdown
of neurochemical molecules
during transport,
affecting the body's motor
functions, autonomic systems
and the brain's
higher reasoning centers.
What are the symptoms?
COMPUTER: Victims suffer
from paranoid delusions,
multi-infarct dementia,
hallucinations...
Hallucinations?
What... what kind of
hallucinations?
COMPUTER: Victims experience
somatic, tactile
and a visual hallucinations,
accompanied by
psychogenic hysteria.
Peripheral symptoms
include sleeplessness,
accelerated heart rate,
diminished eyesight
leading to acute myopia,
painful spasms
in the extremities
and in most cases,
dehydration.
Computer...
what is the treatment
for transporter psychosis?
COMPUTER:
There is no known treatment.
The autopsy showed
residual ionization
in every one of
Lieutenant Kelly's systems.
I think that's what caused
the muscular and systemic
contractions.
From where
did the ionization come?
There's evidence
of electrical burns
on the victim's body,
as if he was exposed
to ionized gas
or high-energy plasma.
Plasma?
There's no way they could
have been exposed...
Unless it was matter
from the streamer.
Is there evidence
of a hull breach?
Could the plasma
from the streamer
have found its way
onto the ship?
No.
Data, what's the report on
that broken sample container?
The analysis of the fragments
is not yet complete.
Captain,
if there's evidence
of similar ionization
in those fragments,
it could mean
that they tried
to beam aboard material
from the streamer.
If the plasma exploded,
that would explain a few things.
Let me know when
the analysis is complete.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
From the look of these
fracture patterns,
I'd say that the explosive force
came from within the container.
The container does
show evidence
of residual
ionization.
I believe your
hypothesis was correct.
It was used to store
high-energy plasma.
LA FORGE:
So they were collecting samples
from the plasma streamer.
But they had
the proper container.
How could it have exploded?
Perhaps we should attempt
to re-create their experiment
to see what happens to matter
when it is beamed aboard
under similar conditions.
LA FORGE:
It's a good idea.
We'll prepare a new container.
Reg, I don't want
to take any chances here.
Start setting up a level-5
containment field
here in Engineering, okay?
Aye, sir.
Are you all right,
Lieutenant?
I'm fine.
Yes, thank you.
Geordi?
Hmm?
Lieutenant Barclay appears
inordinately preoccupied
with his physiological
condition.
I have seen him
check his pulse rate,
as well as his visual
acuity several times
over the last 20 minutes.
Thanks, Data.
Reg?
Yes, sir?
You okay?
I'm just fine, sir.
You look a little pale.
I do?
Look, Reg, it's been
a long couple of days.
Why don't you
get some rest?
We've got everything
under control here.
I think I'll do that, sir.
Thank you.
La Forge to Counselor Troi.
Go ahead, Commander.
Counselor,
do you have a minute?
Lieutenant Barclay,
I've been calling you.
Why haven't you responded?
Reg, what are you doing?
I'm walking.
I can see that.
Where are you going?
Nowhere!
I just don't get to see
these decks very often.
Look, there's
stellar cartography.
I thought that
was Deck 11.
Mr. Barclay...
I was having
trouble sleeping
and I'm trying
to wear myself out.
It is a perfectly normal thing
to be doing, isn't it?
Commander La Forge
said you seemed
a little nervous
this morning.
I'm always nervous.
Everybody knows that.
He also mentioned
that you said
you saw something
in the transporter beam.
Well, I was wrong.
They checked the transporter
and there wasn't...
I mean, there
was nothing there.
I imagined
the whole thing.
You don't sound
very convinced of that.
Listen, Counselor,
I really appreciate
your concern in this matter,
but I wish you wouldn't continue
with this conversation.
I'm really perfectly fine.
Mr. Barclay, you're exhausted
and highly agitated.
And I cannot allow
a member of this crew
to endanger himself
or others.
I'm not endangering anyone else
and I really wish you...
I think it would be
in your best interest
to take a leave of absence.
Reg, I'm temporarily
relieving you of duty.
Fine. Fine.
Do what you have to do,
Counselor.
( sound of sea breeze
and birds chirping )
Computer, more birds.
( chirping becomes
overwhelming )
End stress reduction program.
Water.
COMPUTER: Specify temperature.
I don't care.
Just give me water.
Calm. Calm. Stay calm.
( sighs deeply )
All right, Computer,
let's try some music.
Something soothing.
( soft, tranquil
music begins )
( breathing deeply )
( gasping )
( door opening )
Sir, begging your pardon,
but couldn't this wait
till the morning?
No.
Chief, I've just... I've been
reviewing the transport logs.
What are these... these energy
variations that keep appearing?
There was one when
I was transported to
the science ship, do you see?
Yeah, they're just, uh...
Sorry. They're just
ionic fluctuations--
a result
of our interlock
with the Yosemite's
transporter system.
So a fluctuation occurred
while I was inside
the matter stream.
It's nothing
to worry about, sir.
I need you
to transport me
to the science ship
and then directly back again.
And while
I'm in the beam,
can you re-create one of
those ionic fluctuations?
I guess so, but if you don't
mind my asking, sir, what for?
Well, I...
Commander La Forge
wants some tricorder readings
on those fluctuations.
We can do that
from right here.
No, I... the transporter sensors
may not be sensitive enough.
Now, I'm giving you an order,
Mr. O'Brien.
Aye, sir.
If you don't mind my making
an observation, sir,
you forgot to bring
a tricorder.
Either there's
something in there
or I'm going crazy,
and I've just got to know.
You can understand that,
can't you?
Yes, sir, I can.
Stand by, sir.
I want you to wake
the senior staff.
...and, and then I saw it
again just 20 minutes ago.
It was the same exact thing,
just moving around
in the transporter beam.
Let me get this straight.
You think this
thing was alive?
It... it... it was...
dark and distorted
and it had what looked
like a mouth.
A mouth...
I don't see anything
wrong with his arm.
Reg, why did you wait so long
to tell anybody about your arm?
Well... I...
I thought
I was hallucinating.
That I... had, um...
That it was
transporter psychosis,
but now I know what I saw
in there was real.
I was the only one
who experienced
ionic fluctuations
in the transport.
Maybe that's why
no one else saw it.
Mr. Barclay, I've been told
that you've been under
considerable strain
during the past few days.
Isn't it possible
that you simply imagined...
I know what you're going
to say, Captain.
I know I've been acting
strange lately,
but you've got to
believe me
that I would never
have called you in here
unless I was
absolutely certain.
Mr. La Forge,
get Mr. O'Brien.
Take that transporter
system apart
piece by piece
if you have to.
Mr. Worf, I want
a level-3 security alert
until further notice.
Aye, sir.
I'll run a micro-cellular scan
of Mr. Barclay's arm.
It might take some time, but if
there's a problem, I'll find it.
Keep me apprised.
Dismissed.
I'm picking up minute levels
of residual ionization
from the subdermal tissue
of his left arm.
The patterns
correspond exactly
to those we measured
in Lieutenant Kelly's body
and in the sample container
from the science ship.
There's no question--
you have been exposed
to the same high energy
plasma they were.
So something did happen to me
in the transporter beam.
You might have been exposed to
something from the science ship.
You did say something touched
your left arm during transport.
And that's exactly where
the ionization is focused.
Does this ionization pose
a threat to Mr. Barclay?
It might.
I'll have to run a base-pair
correlation to see
if there's any sign
of DNA breakdown.
Sir, Commander
La Forge and I
were planning to re-create
the circumstances
of the explosion
on the Yosemite.
And that might
give us some answers.
Permission to continue
with the experiment?
Granted.
Tell Mr. O'Brien to take all the
primary transporters off-line.
I don't want to risk
any further contaminations.
Make sure you take all the
necessary safety precautions.
Aye, sir.
I'd like you to wear
this monitoring device.
It will tell me if there is
the slightest sign
of increased ionization.
Yes, Doctor.
Structural reinforcement
is at 240%.
Activating
containment field.
Well, that should do it.
Okay, Reg,
we've locked on
to the coordinates
of the plasma streamer.
Go ahead and beam aboard
a sample, will you?
Aye, sir.
Okay.
What would they
have done first?
Standard analysis begins with
a resonance frequency scan.
That sounds like a good place
to start. Let's do that.
Initiating
resonance sweep.
Frequency
range at...
Barclay, check
the containment field.
The field is at
its maximum limit,
but it is holding!
My visor's picking up
biomagnetic energy.
Highly complex
patterns.
You know, I think
these things are alive.
Reg?
Reg!
Reg...
Life-forms?
That is correct.
They appear to be
quasi-energy microbes
that exist within the distortion
field of the plasma streamer.
We didn't detect them
until we tried to run
the resonance
frequency scan.
Apparently, they didn't
like it very much.
They shattered
the sample container.
Which caused
a plasma explosion
similar to the one
on the science ship.
Exactly.
When we linked up with
their transporter system,
one or more of the microbes must
have gotten into our system.
We think they're still
caught in the buffer.
It might explain
what you saw.
But what I saw
was much bigger
than a microbe.
Normal spatial
relationships
are often distorted
within the matter stream.
Your perceptions may have
been exaggerated.
Some of these microbes
are also in
your body, Reg.
In... inside me?
They were in Lieutenant
Kelly's body as well.
That's what caused the
contractions during the autopsy.
The biofilters should have
screened them out,
but it didn't.
The microbes exist
simultaneously as both
matter and energy.
The biofilter cannot distinguish
them from the matter stream.
Right, but if
we held Barclay
suspended in
mid-transport,
at the point where matter starts
to lose molecular cohesion...
The molecules would begin
to omit nucleonic particles.
We may be able to
derive a pattern
the computer
would recognize.
LA FORGE: And then reprogram
the biofilters and screen
the microbes out.
I think
this'll work, Reg.
Suspend me?
I don't like
the sound of this.
Well, we would have to
keep you in there for a while.
How long?
30, 40 seconds--
it's tough to tell.
But I think
it'd be safe.
But if-- if I'm in
the matter stream too long...
Your pattern would degrade
to the point
where your signal
would be permanently lost.
After 15 seconds or so
in the beam,
you may start to
feel lightheaded.
Try to stay calm.
Oh, and it's important
not to move around too much.
Right.
Initializing the backup
pattern buffer.
Holding at standby.
You ready, Reg?
Energize.
Molecular resolution
at 60%.
Engaging static mode.
His pattern is
locked and holding.
Starting biofilter scan.
Signal's holding.
The imagining scanner still
haven't isolated the microbes.
I'll try increasing
molecular dispersion.
His signal resolution's
down to 55%.
Don't worry,
I can hold him together.
Commander, his signal
resolution's down to 50%.
We need to bring him back.
I know, I know.
Just give me
one more second.
We need more dispersion.
Increase phase
transition frequency.
Aye, sir.
The imagining scanners
are actuating.
Got it.
Pattern acquisition
positive.
Programming biofilter.
Don't worry, Reg,
this won't hurt a bit.
I'm reading a 92%
increase in mass.
There is something
in the beam with him.
Security to
Transporter Room three.
WORF: Right away.
I'm setting up a force field
around the chamber.
Drop the force field.
There are more
crew members in the beam.
You have to grab them
and hold on.
Understood.
Follow me.
Reg, what happened?
Well, when I...
when I saw that there was
more than one of them,
I... I thought
maybe the other crew
were trying to do
the same thing that we were.
We're infected
with something.
Lieutenant Kelly tried to
reprogram the biofilter.
It looks like he pushed
molecular dispersion
past the integrity point.
Your patterns
got caught in the beam.
The residual energy
from the plasma stream,
it must have amplified
the charge in the buffer
enough to keep your patterns
from degrading.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46043.6:
The reprogrammed biofilter
was effective in removing
the alien microbes
from Mr. Barclay
and the four crew members.
The microbes have been
returned to the plasma stream.
Chief.
Lieutenant.
I'm glad
you could make it.
You know, I think this is
the first time we've ever spoken
outside of
the Transporter Room.
Well, to be honest,
I've always avoided you.
Why?
Because you run the transporters
and I hate the transporters.
At least I used to.
So what's in the box?
I think you might like
to meet Christina.
Christina,
Lieutenant Barclay.
It's your pet spider.
Lycosa tarantula.
Don't worry,
she won't bite.
She's...
very large.
I found her on Titus IV.
I almost stepped on her
by accident.
Oh, I'll get us
a couple of drinks, okay?
Keep an eye on her,
will you?
Sure.
Uh, Chief?