Captain's Log,
Stardate 46071.6.
We have been called
to the aid of a transport ship
which has been attacked
near Rekag-Seronia.
Hostilities between
the two factions on that planet
have intensified recently
threatening an important
Federation shipping route.
Captain, sensors have located
the transport ship.
Two Rekag battle cruisers
are flanking it.
Red Alert!
Shields up.
Phasers on line.
Photon torpedoes
armed and ready.
Is the transport
still under attack?
The cruisers' weapons
are powered up...
Sir, the Rekag ships
are turning
and heading out
of sensor range.
They don't want
to take on the Enterprise.
DATA:
We are now within
visual range
of the transport, sir.
On screen.
Sensors indicate
damage
to the Dorian's
subspace emitter.
Audio communication
only, sir.
Open a channel, Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
Captain Talmadge of the Dorian.
Glad you're here.
We took some shield damage
from the Rekag ships,
but we're still intact.
Do you have
any injuries?
Can we assist you in any way?
No injuries,
but I'd like permission
to transport
two of our passengers
to your ship.
Of course.
We're conveying a mediator
to Seronia.
I think he's the reason
the Rekags fired on us.
( signal breaking up )
...traveled... negotiations...
Captain, I'm losing you.
Go ahead and beam
your passengers on board.
Counselor, after you've seen
to their needs
will you escort them
to my ready room.
Yes, Captain.
RIKER:
Cancel Red Alert.
Mr. Worf, take
the weapons off-line.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
I'm Counselor Deanna Troi.
Ambassador Ves Alkar...
and my mother,
Sev Maylor.
Counselor, it's imperative
that I speak to the Captain.
You think he's
attracted to you
but he isn't.
You offer him nothing.
ALKAR:
She's hasn't been
feeling well.
Could she be taken
to quarters?
Of course.
Chief.
I'll take you to Captain Picard.
Mother, go with her.
Don't pursue him.
I won't have it.
I'll stop you.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I'm grateful for the
Federation's offer to escort me
but if I arrive on Rekag-Seronia
on board the Enterprise--
the armed flagship
of Starfleet--
my mission as negotiator
of peace will be compromised.
There must be
a Federation transport ship
somewhere in the area
that could take me there.
With all due respect...
Admiral, to put the Ambassador
on board
another unarmed transport
would be to invite
a second assault.
I believe the attack on us
was an isolated incident
nothing more.
Ambassador Alkar,
the Rekag-Seronia dispute
has threatened Federation ships
for many months.
We are grateful
that you are willing
to undertake this mission
and you have our full support.
Thank you, sir.
However, we also recognize
that safety is an issue--
not just yours,
but the crew that escorts you.
To send you
on an unarmed transport
puts everyone at risk.
I think it best
if you proceed to Rekag-Seronia
aboard the Enterprise.
Then I have no choice.
Once you get to Rekag-Seronia
you can conduct your
negotiations as you see fit.
Until then, you'll be in good
hands with Captain Picard.
I understand, sir.
Good luck,
and a successful journey.
Picard
to Commander Riker.
Yes, sir?
Set a course for Seronia.
Aye, sir.
WORF:
That will be
all for today.
There will be another class
tomorrow at 0700 hours.
The skills
are demanding.
You're very
disciplined.
I believe in a strong connection
between body and mind.
You obviously share
the same convictions.
Yes, I do.
Only sometimes, my body
has a problem conforming
to my mind's wishes.
( chuckling )
I would imagine that
your self-discipline
helps you in your work.
I don't know about that.
I think maybe my biggest
asset is patience.
I'll let everyone talk
until they're exhausted
and, when I start, they're
too tired to argue.
You're going to need
all your patience in Seronia.
I can't imagine
how you're going
to get those two sides
talking to each other.
Neither can I.
I won't know that
until we get there.
I tend to feel my way
through a situation.
Deck nine.
If I were empathic, like you
I'd have a real advantage.
I thought Lumerians
were empathic.
Only with each other,
not other species
so I don't have any idea
what you might
be feeling just now.
Curiosity.
What I sense from you
is very unusual--
calmness, serenity,
tranquility.
You seem to embody
the very qualities
that you hope to
draw out in others.
Tell me, Counselor
have you ever been involved
in diplomatic negotiations?
Several times,
with Captain Picard.
There have been instances
when having an empath along
has been helpful.
I'm sure.
I could use
some of that help.
Would you come with me
when we reach Seronia?
If the Captain
authorizes it
of course I will.
Good.
I hope to see you again.
You're late!
Mother, I told you
that I'd be gone
for over an hour.
You're late because of her.
Have you mated with him yet?
What?
That's what you want, isn't it?
Mother...
please, come in.
I can always tell--
the ones with a certain
look in their eye.
I'd better go.
Mother, please...
And I'll tell you this.
If you do,
you'll regret it
the rest of your life.
Mother, come in,
please.
You should lie down.
( door chiming )
Come in.
Hi.
It's that time again.
The dreaded crew
evaluation reports.
Oh, does it have to be today?
It's not going to be
any easier tomorrow.
It might.
What's wrong?
I've just had
a disturbing encounter
with Alkar's mother.
She frightens me, Will.
The feelings I
sense from her
are malevolent.
They're out of proportion.
They're evil.
Well, I know she's been
sick, and she's very old.
She's probably senile.
Who knows, we could all
end up that way someday.
You're right.
Okay, let's get through
these evaluations
and when we're done
I'm going to reward myself
with two ice cream sundaes.
First, molecular biology.
Lieutenant Jeffrey Fratis.
Worf to Commander Riker.
Go ahead.
Can you report
to Ambassador Alkar's quarters?
There is an emergency.
We're on our way.
40 cc's inaprovaline.
I'm sorry, Ambassador.
She was ill.
I never should have
brought her along.
She was 93.
She'd lived
a long life.
I should be grateful
for that.
Alkar, is there
anything I can do?
Counselor, there's
a funeral meditation--
part of our rituals.
As an empath
you're the only person
on board
who could perform it
with me.
I'll be glad to help.
This meditation is one
of our most sacred ceremonies.
Hold the stone like this.
Rohm gah, sevi rohm.
Say after me.
An end to grief...
an end to pain...
strength comes from love...
...and courage from wisdom.
Thank you.
( sighs )
Computer,
today's appointment calendar.
0900 hours, counseling session
with Ensign Janeway.
1000 hours,
counseling session...
Cancel them.
Cancel everything
till after lunch.
Acknowledged.
You wanted to
see me, Doctor?
Yes, Captain.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but I'm a little concerned.
I haven't been
able to determine
the cause of death.
She was elderly,
and Alkar said
she had been ill
but I found no evidence
of any disease.
I did find abnormally
high levels
of neurotransmitter residue
in her cerebral cortex.
What are you suggesting?
I'd like to do
an autopsy.
I've already
spoken to Alkar
and he informs me
Lumerian custom forbids it.
Could you speak
with him?
You suspect that her death
poses some kind of threat
to the Enterprise?
Well...
No.
Then we have no alternative
but to concur with his wishes.
( door opens )
Deanna.
Hello.
Come in, please.
I thought you might
like some company
if you're not too busy.
Nothing that can't wait.
Would you like
something to drink?
No.
I'd like you to talk to me.
About?
About you.
I don't know anything
about you
and I'd like to.
There's very
little to know.
I lead a very
simple life.
What kind of woman
do you find attractive?
Do you find me attractive?
Extremely.
And when you find
someone attractive
what do you usually do?
That depends on
a lot of things.
Is it really
so complicated?
It can be.
Well, perhaps
you overthink things.
Deanna...
Yes?
I'm sorry
if I led you
to believe...
You are very beautiful...
but our relationship
can't be like that.
Deck four.
Sir.
Will.
We were supposed to finish
the crew evaluation reports.
Of course. Come in.
Sir!
As you were.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
I was just leaving.
If there's
anything else I need
I know where
to find you.
Yes, ma'am.
Are you bothered
by his being here?
Of course not.
Good, because it's really
none of your business.
I know that.
I believe we were with
Lieutenant Fratis
in molecular biology.
Why do I think
you're upset?
I don't know.
Could we just continue
with the evaluation?
Will, remember who
you're talking to.
You are bothered,
I can tell.
Deanna, I'm sorry I intruded.
When you're ready to work,
why don't you give me a call?
I will.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46073.6.
We have arrived
without incident
at Rekag-Seronia
where two members
of Ambassador Alkar's
delegation have been waiting.
They have joined us
to report on the situation
in the capital city.
Things have
deteriorated steadily.
Rekag sympathizers
in outlying districts
have attacked
several towns.
But I was
under the impression
that there was
a cease-fire agreement.
Oh, it was broken before
it went into effect.
A Rekag shuttle strayed
into Seronian space
and was destroyed
by fighter craft.
Naturally,
the Rekags retaliated.
There's been fighting
ever since.
If they would just
sit down with me...
The Rekags won't go into
Seronian territory for talks
and the Seronians
won't go to Rekag.
In the meantime, they fight.
Ambassador, the situation
sounds so volatile.
Perhaps
a cooling-off period...
These people need an end
to the fighting now.
To delay a week,
even a few days
could cost
thousands of lives.
Then I would recommend
that we ask both sides
if they would agree
to meet in
the city of Darthen.
Why Darthen?
It's a coastal city.
It has been neutral
throughout the conflict.
Both Seronians
and Rekag loyalists live there.
It might be acceptable
as a compromise.
Contact their leaders.
If they will meet
me in Darthen
I will join them
there tomorrow.
I know it must be
my imagination
but it seems as though
Lieutenant Pinder
just doesn't want me
in his section.
What makes you
think that?
He's so critical.
I can't ever do anything
to please him
and I try, Counselor.
I try to make sure
there's nothing
he could find
fault with.
Give me an example
of what you mean.
Well, yesterday
I was running
routine diagnostics
on the sensor pallets.
They checked out
but Lieutenant Pinder
questioned me
because I'd allowed
a .023 variance.
That's well within
specifications.
He goes out of his way
to criticize me.
Do you know of any reason
why he might do that?
No. That's why I'm here.
Well, maybe he's just tired
of hearing you complain.
Pardon me?
I know I'm certainly tired
of it.
How do you think it feels
to sit and listen
to someone whine about
themselves all the time?
I didn't realize I was...
This isn't
Starfleet Academy.
You're not going
to be coddled.
If you can't take it here
then you might think
about a transport ship.
There's a lot
less pressure there.
But I love being
on the Enterprise.
I don't want to be
anywhere else.
If you aren't up to it, then
you don't deserve to be here
isn't that right?
I guess so.
So you'd better take ahold
of yourself
or be prepared for transfer.
I will, Counselor.
Thank you.
( door opens, closes )
Glad I could help.
Yeah, here we go.
Biofilter log
on Sev Maylor.
Geordi, could this
log have been damaged
in any way?
I don't think so.
Why do you ask?
There's a discrepancy
between the log
and the tricorder readings I
took just three days later.
The tricorder shows massive
physiological deterioration
compared with her condition
when she beamed aboard.
I find it hard to believe
that so much damage
could have occurred
in such a short
period of time.
Well, I can run a diagnostic
on the biofilter system
and your tricorder.
Thanks. Of course,
the best way
to get the
information I need
would be to do
an autopsy.
Ambassador, we've
received word
from the Seronian and
the Rekag delegates.
They've agreed
to meet with you
in Darthen tomorrow.
Thank you, Commander.
Counselor Troi has
altered her appearance.
Am I interrupting?
Hello, Counselor.
You want him
I can tell
but you have nothing
to give him.
Deanna, could I talk
to you in private...?
And you, you're
envious of him.
You pretend to support him
but secretly
you want him to fail.
That's not so.
Please...
You must return
to your quarters.
I won't. I want to be
here with you.
Ambassador!
The Counselor and I
are needed on the Bridge.
Of course, Commander.
I don't know what you thought
you were doing in there
but you were
way out of line.
Deck nine.
All right, Deanna, just
what the hell is all this?
Imzadi...
do you still care
about me?
Of course I
care about you.
I'm worried about you.
What's all this?
Don't you think
I'm attractive?
This just isn't you.
Oh... oh, it is.
You want me, don't you?
Deanna...
I need you.
( yells )
What is this?
Please!
( door chimes )
Come in.
Deanna, I'm leaving
for the surface.
You said
you'd take me with you.
I know,
but that's not possible now.
You said I'd be helpful.
You needed me.
And I still do.
You've done so much for me.
Then take me.
Don't leave me here.
Is Liva going with you?
She's been on
Seronia for weeks.
She knows the people,
the situation.
She wants to take you
away from me.
Deanna
you are my anchor.
I need you more than you
could possibly realize.
Do you understand?
I need you here
making it possible
for me to do my work.
I won't let her have you!
I'll stop her!
I will go with you!
Take me with you!
Please, Alkar!
Don't leave me!
Don't do this!
No!
You wouldn't have
recognized her.
Her dress
her hair...
everything about her wa...
I'm closer to Deanna
than I've ever been to anyone
and last night, she was someone
that I had never seen before.
And you don't know
of anything
that might have caused her
to behave like that?
No. I've thought
and thought about it.
I don't have an answer.
Computer, location
of Counselor Troi.
Deck six, corridor B.
Let's go.
Ambassador, I came to alert
you that the Rekags
and the Seronians
are in disagreement
about the seating arrangements
at the conference table.
I'm not surprised.
The good news however
is that the cease-fire
seems to be holding.
And that is by far
the best news.
Thank you, Captain.
Chief.
Will you take me with you?
Deanna.
Deanna, I already
told you...
I won't let her have you.
( cries out )
( Troi grunting )
Security to
Transporter Room Two.
Don't try and stop me!
No!
Let go!
It's nothing.
It's superficial.
What happened to Deanna?
All of the systems
in her body
have elevated readings.
Take her to Sick Bay.
I want to see you
in Sick Bay, too.
Captain, perhaps we should delay
transporting to the surface.
No.
You should proceed
with your mission.
Very well.
Chief, transport them
to the planet's surface.
Aye, sir.
CRUSHER:
We'll have
to sedate her.
20 cc's melorazine.
Yes, Doctor.
How's it feeling?
It's a little stiff,
but it'll be fine.
It'll disappear
in a day or two.
OGAWA:
Dr. Crusher.
I think you should see
these readings, Doctor.
Her neurotransmitter levels
are 300% above normal.
If you remember,
I found extremely high levels
of neurotransmitter residue
in Alkar's mother.
Could Deanna have picked up
some disease from her?
I don't know.
I need to do that autopsy.
I don't care about the customs
of Alkar's people.
I need to find out
if there's a connection
between what killed Maylor
and what's happening to Troi.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here, Captain.
Mr. Worf, contact
Ambassador Alkar.
I need to speak with him.
Doctor
neural energy is now
340% above normal.
WORF:
Captain, Ambassador Alkar
is at the negotiation table
and cannot be disturbed.
Proceed with
the autopsy.
CRUSHER:
Medical Log, Stardate 46075.1.
I have performed an autopsy
on Alkar's mother
but instead
of answering our questions
the results have created
an even deeper mystery.
I don't have
any explanation for this.
When I examined Maylor's body
I found her heart, her lungs,
her skeletal structure
most of the systems in her body
were those of a 30 year old.
But how could that be?
We both saw the woman.
That's not all.
I compared Maylor
and Alkar's DNA.
I don't know who that woman was
but she was definitely
not his mother.
Deanna's condition
is deteriorating rapidly.
She could die.
There are questions
that only Alkar can answer.
Picard to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here, Captain.
Meet me in Transporter Room Two.
We're going down to the surface.
Aye, sir.
No, she wasn't my mother.
And she wasn't
93 years old.
Captain, did you
perform an autopsy
against my wishes?
Yes, for a very
good reason.
Counselor Deanna Troi
is in Sick Bay, dying.
Dr. Crusher doesn't know
the cause of her condition
but I believe you do.
Alkar, we need you.
The Rekags have withdrawn
some of their concessions
and the Seronians
are threatening
to break off the talks.
I'll be right there.
But...
They've been arguing
for hours in there.
It seems hopeless.
But now, when
expectations are lowest
now is the moment
I can be most effective.
If I am focused, centered,
free of disquieting thoughts
I can turn these
factions toward peace.
Alkar...
Hear me out, Captain.
It's important you understand.
You see, I
discovered long ago
I had the ability to channel
my darker thoughts--
my unwanted emotions-- to
others,
leaving
me unencumbered.
Is this what you've been doing
to Counselor Troi?
I hadn't planned it.
I'd expected Maylor to live
through the negotiation.
Her death could not
have been more untimely.
So then, you deliberately
used Deanna.
She's an empath.
I was reasonably certain
I could establish
a link with her
and frankly, I was amazed
when I saw how
quickly she'd aged.
Usually my receptacles
survive for years.
Receptacles?
Oh, come now, Captain.
Surely you can see
there's a broader canvas here.
If I came to these peace talks
hindered by unwanted emotions
then the Rekags
and Seronians
would be condemned
to go on fighting.
You cannot explain away
a wantonly immoral act
because you think
that it is connected
to some higher purpose.
Captain, do you know
how many people have died
on this planet
in the last 48 hours?
Thousands.
Deanna Troi
is just one individual.
That does not justify
brutalizing her
nor any of the others
you have used.
Ask the Seronian
and Rekag children
who go to bed each night
in fear of their lives.
Captain, I get
no payment.
I have no power base,
no agenda.
I am willing to risk my life
simply to help others.
Do you think that makes you
appear courageous?
Because you're mistaken.
You're a coward, Alkar.
You exploit
the innocent
because you're unwilling
to shoulder the burdens
of unpleasant emotions.
Well, this time
you will be held accountable.
I'm taking you back
to the Enterprise
to release Counselor Troi.
I have no intention
of releasing her now, or ever.
Alkar
everything is falling apart.
You have to come now.
If you'll excuse me, Captain.
Mr. Wor...
I'm needed.
You and your security chief
will leave.
Lock onto Alkar's signal
and bring him on board.
Captain, I am sure
the Seronians
have reactivated
their security field.
Then work with Mr. La Forge
to find a way to break through.
I want that man
on this ship.
Aye, sir.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
If Alkar is flooding her
with this psychic waste
that would explain the high
level of neurotransmitters.
All these negative emotions
pouring into her
have caused a
chemical response
in her brain.
Isn't there something
you can do to counteract it?
Enzymic decontaminants
would be able to reduce
the level of neurotransmitters
but I can't make any headway
unless Alkar stops
what he's doing.
He has no intention
of stopping.
He feels perfectly
justified
in using her
until she dies.
Then Deanna has to die.
In order to save
Deanna
Alkar has to break his link
with her
and the only way
he can only do that
is if she's no longer
an adequate receptacle.
When Maylor died, Alkar turned
immediately to Deanna.
If Deanna dies
and he breaks
the link with her
then he will choose
someone else
possibly someone
from his own delegation.
Wait a minute--
you're talking about
killing Deanna.
I'll be able
to resuscitate her, Will
as long as it's not more
than 30 minutes
but the big question is
will that be enough time?
Alkar has to establish
a link with someone else
before we revive Deanna
or else he might
turn back to her.
We must bear in mind
that we'll be putting
his next victim at risk.
I want every possible
security measure taken
to protect that person.
How will you...?
I'll give her a hypospray
of dylamadon.
It's the gentlest way.
Proceed, Doctor.
Well, my friend
an era of bloodshed and conflict
appears to be over.
Alkar...!
What is it?
I'm fine...
just a little light-headed.
You're exhausted.
Do you want a doctor?
No, no, of course not.
PICARD:
Enterprise to Ambassador Alkar.
Respond, sir.
I'm here, Captain.
Ambassador, you must return
to the Enterprise immediately.
Counselor Troi is dying.
We are prepared to transport you
from the surface
whether you come willingly
or not.
There are security
force fields
protecting
us, Captain.
They won't protect you
any longer.
Transporter Room Two,
prepare to energize.
We're ready, Captain.
( door opens )
Computer, make a note.
Death occurred
at 1430 hours
from respiratory
and renal failure.
Will you wait for me
in my quarters?
Of course.
It's a tragic loss
but her death had a purpose.
I intend
to make certain
that you answer
for what you have done.
Your own Federation Council
has promised me
a safe and timely passage
back to my planet.
I expect you to honor that,
Captain.
How much longer
do we have?
Three minutes
and 40 seconds.
Transporter Room Two,
I want you to lock
onto the young woman in
Ambassador Alkar's quarters.
We may have to transport
her out of there.
Yes, Captain.
Mr. Worf, I want you
to station yourself
outside her quarters.
Aye, sir.
She helped me so much.
Without her, I couldn't have
accomplished what I did.
I'm so sorry.
Is there anything I can do?
Yes.
There is something.
If we could share
the funeral meditation...
CRUSHER:
We have a minute
and a half left.
Prepare a hypospray
of cordrazine.
We'll use that in conjunction
with the cortical stimulators.
Yes, Doctor.
Rohm gah...
sevi rohm...
rohm gah.
Rohm gah...
sevi rohm...
rohm gah.
We can't wait any longer.
Release the stasis field.
Yes, Doctor.
10 cc's cordrazine.
Cortical stimulators.
Now.
An end...
an end to pain...
An end to pain...
Again.
She has a pulse.
Blood pressure climbing.
90 over 40.
Cortical activity
approaching normal levels.
Let's neutralize
the neurotransmitters.
Initiate
decontamination sequence.
Levels are dropping,
Doctor.
Down to 420% above normal.
390%...
Picard
to Transporter Room Three.
Not yet.
We won't know
if it's working
till the levels
are below 300%.
Alkar!
Alkar, what's wrong?
OGAWA:
Neurotransmitter levels
are down to 310%...
290%.
Now.
Picard to Transporter
Room Three, energize.
Let me go!
Neurotransmitter levels
are down to 230%.
( groaning )
Worf to Captain Picard.
Ambassador Alkar is dead.
Will...
Beverly thinks Alkar
must have been
at a susceptible point
in the meditation ceremony
when he was vulnerable.
Then the flow of
negative emotions
and feelings were reversed
back to him somehow.
That's our guess.
Like a man
with no immune system
he wasn't able to handle
the overload.
And Liva?
She seems to be fine.
He wasn't able to establish
a link on her.
Looking back on
the past few days
it's as though I'm looking
at a holodeck projection
of someone else.
That's how it seemed
to all of us.
Thanks for sticking by me.
I always will...
even when you're
old and gray.