Captain, I have
identified the signal.
It is from
the USS Jenolan--
a Federation
transport ship
reported missing in
this sector 75 years ago.
Code one alpha zero--
ship in distress.
Take us out of warp,
Ensign, all stop.
Aye, sir.
Report.
We have entered a massive
gravitational field, Captain.
There are no stars
or other stellar bodies
listed on our
navigational charts.
However, sensors indicate the
presence of an extremely strong
gravitational source
in this vicinity.
Can you localize the source
of the gravitational field?
RIKER:
Sensors?
DATA:
I am having difficulty
scanning the object.
It appears to be
approximately
200 million kilometers
in diameter.
That's nearly as large as the
Earth's orbit around the sun.
Why didn't we detect this
before now?
The object's enormous mass
is causing a great deal
of gravimetric interference.
That might have prevented
our sensors from detecting it
before we dropped
out of warp.
Mr. Data...
could this be
a Dyson sphere?
The object does fit the general
parameters of Dyson's theory.
A Dyson sphere?
It's a very old theory,
Number One.
I'm not surprised
that you haven't heard of it.
In the 20th century,
a physicist called Freeman Dyson
postulated the theory
that an enormous,
hollow sphere could be
constructed around a star.
This would have
the advantage of harnessing
all the radiant energy
of that star,
and any population living
on the interior surface
would have virtually
inexhaustible sources of power.
Are you saying you think there
are people living in there?
Possibly a great number
of people, Commander.
The interior surface area
of a sphere this size
is the equivalent of more than
250 million Class-M planets.
Sir, I have located
the distress signal.
It is coming from a point
in the northern hemisphere.
Ensign Rager, put us
into synchronous orbit
above that position.
RAGER: Aye, sir.
I have located
the Jenolan, sir.
It has impacted on
the surface of the sphere.
PICARD:
Magnify.
DATA:
There are no life signs.
However, there are several
small power emanations,
and life support is still
functioning on minimal levels.
Riker to Engineering.
Geordi,
join us in
Transporter Room three.
Mr. Worf.
This air is pretty stale.
Life support is
barely operating.
See if you can increase
the oxygen level.
Aye, sir.
Commander.
The transporter is
still online.
It's being fed power from
the auxiliary systems.
The rematerialization
subroutine has been disabled.
Yeah, and that's not all.
The phase inducers are connected
to the emitter array.
The override is
completely gone,
and the pattern
buffer's been locked
into a continuous
diagnostic cycle.
This doesn't
make any sense.
Locking the unit
into a diagnostic mode
just sends the matter array
through a pattern buffer.
Why would anyone...
There's a pattern
in the buffer still.
It's completely intact.
There's less than .003%
signal degradation.
How is that possible?
I don't know.
I've never seen
a transporter
jury-rigged
like this before.
Could someone survive
inside a transporter buffer
for 75 years?
I know a way
to find out.
( transporter energizing )
Space...
the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Well, thank you, lads.
Oh, well, we got to get
Franklin out of there.
Someone else's pattern
is still in the buffer?
Aye, Matt Franklin.
We went in together.
( console beeping )
Something's wrong.
One of the inducers
has failed.
Boost the gain
on the matter stream.
Come on, Franklin.
I know you're still
in there.
( sighs )
It's no use.
His pattern has
degraded 53%.
He's gone.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
He was a good lad.
I'm Commander William Riker,
starship Enterprise.
Lieutenant Commander
Geordi La Forge.
The Enterprise?
I should have known.
I bet Jim Kirk himself
hauled the old gal
out of mothballs
to come looking for me.
Captain Montgomery Scott.
Tell me, how long
have I been missing?
Well...
WORF: Sir.
I have restored
life support.
The oxygen levels will
return to normal shortly.
Captain Scott,
Lieutenant Worf.
Lieutenant?
Yes.
Captain, perhaps there are a
few things we should talk about.
We should probably
get you to Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher will
want to have...
You've changed
the resonator array.
Geordi, I think our guest
is going to have
a lot of
engineering questions.
Not to worry, Commander,
I'll take care of him.
What have you done with
the duotronic enhancers?
Well, those were replaced
with isolinear chips
about 40 years ago.
It's a lot more
efficient now.
Oh! That's an EPS
power tap there.
Ah.
So you were saying
a little earlier
that you were on your way
to the Norpin colony
when you experienced
warp engine failure?
Aye, that's right.
See, we had an overload
in one of the plasma
transfer conduits,
and the captain
brought us out of warp,
and we hit some
gravimetric interference,
and there it was,
as big as life.
Oh, is that
a conduit interface?
Yeah, it is.
You were saying,
it's "as big as life."
You mean
the Dyson sphere.
Aye, an actual
Dyson sphere.
Can you imagine
the engineering skills
needed to even design
such a structure?
Yeah, I know.
It's pretty amazing.
So, what happened when
you first approached it?
Well, we began our standard
survey of the surface,
and we were just completing
the initial orbital scan
when our aft power coil
suddenly exploded.
The ship got caught
in the sphere's gravity well,
and down we went.
Franklin and I were
the only ones
to survive the crash.
Can I ask you
a question?
What in the world
made you think
of using the transporter
pattern buffer to survive?
Well, we...
didn't have enough supplies
to wait for the rescue,
so we had to think
of something.
Yeah, but locking it
into a diagnostic cycle
so that the pattern
wouldn't degrade
and then cross-connecting it
with the phase inducers
to provide a regenerative
power source...
that's absolutely
brilliant.
Well, I think it was
only 50% brilliant
'cause Franklin
deserves better.
You know, I think
you're going to enjoy
the 24th century, Mr. Scott.
We've made some pretty
incredible advances
these last 80 years.
Well, from what
I've seen,
you've got a fine ship,
Mr. La Forge.
A real beauty here.
I must admit to being
a bit overwhelmed.
Hmm. Wait till you
see the Holodeck.
You have a hairline
fracture of the humerus.
It will ache for
a couple of days,
but it should be fine.
Oh, thank you.
Well, I'll say this
about your Enterprise--
the doctors are
a fair sight prettier.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard.
Welcome aboard
the Enterprise, Captain Scott.
Thank you, sir,
and call me Scotty.
How are you feeling?
I don't know.
How am I feeling?
Other than a few
bumps and bruises,
I'd say you feel fine
for a man of 147.
And I don't feel
a day over 120.
I must say,
I was a little surprised
when Commander Riker
told me that you were
on board the Jenolan.
Our records didn't show you
listed as a member of the crew.
Well, I was never actually
a member of the crew.
I was...
just a passenger.
I was heading
for Norpin V
to settle down
and enjoy my retirement.
I see. Well, I would
very much enjoy
the opportunity of hearing
you talk about your career.
I'm sure you would have
some fascinating insights
into the events
of your time.
I'd be happy to.
Good.
Well, I look forward to it.
Excuse me.
Commander,
we need to begin
a full spectrograph analysis
of the Dyson sphere.
I'll get right on it, sir.
Good.
Once again,
welcome on board, Captain.
Sir.
I need to get down
to Engineering and
begin that analysis.
Engineering?
I thought you'd never ask.
( groans )
Captain, the first thing
you need to get
is some rest.
Now, this has been
a shock to your system
and I want you
to not push yourself.
We're pretty busy down there
anyway, Captain Scott.
I promise I'd be happy
to give you a tour
just as soon as
the doctor says it's okay.
I'll find someone to show you
your quarters.
Aye.
This is the food replicator
and your computer terminal.
Good Lord, man.
Where have you put me?
These are standard
guest quarters, sir.
I can try and find something
bigger if you want.
Bigger?
In my day,
even an admiral
wouldn't've had
such quarters on a starship.
You know,
I remember a time
we had to transport
the Dohlman of Elas.
You never heard anyone
whine and complain so much
about quarters
as she did.
The Holodecks,
Ten Forward,
and the gymnasium are
all at your disposal.
The computer can tell you
how to find them.
Until we issue you
a combadge,
just use one of these panels
if you need anything.
You know,
these quarters remind me
of a hotel room
in Argelius.
Oh, now there is a planet--
everything a man wants
right at his fingertips.
'Course on the first visit, I
got into a wee bit of trouble...
Excuse me, sir, but I have
to return to duty.
Oh.
Well, then...
thank you.
I want you to shut down
the warp engines
and recalibrate
the aft sensors
while I work on
the lateral array.
Aye, sir.
BARTEL:
Can I help you, sir?
SCOTTY: Oh, I don't
think so, lassie,
but I'll let you know
if you can.
BARTEL: Sir, this area is
restricted to authorized...
Bartel, it's okay.
I'll handle it.
Captain Scott,
this really isn't...
We're in Engineering.
Call me Scotty.
Scotty, this really isn't
a good time for a tour.
We're running a phase seven
survey of the Dyson sphere.
I'm not here
for a tour, laddie.
I'm here to help.
That's very kind,
but I'm sure
we can handle it.
I was a Starfleet engineer
for 52 years,
Mr. La Forge.
I think I'm still useful.
You're right,
we'd be grateful
for any help
you could give us.
Good.
Let's get to work.
Sensors indicate the presence
of a G-type star
at the center of the sphere.
There also appears to be
a Class-M atmosphere
clinging to
the interior surface.
Is there any indication
that the sphere is inhabited?
Not as yet, sir.
Our preliminary data suggests
it is still capable
of supporting life,
but we have been unable
to find any definite
signs of current
habitation.
Mr. Data, send out
a series of Class-4 probes
to survey the far side
of the sphere.
Perhaps we'll have
more luck with them.
Aye, sir.
Adjust the frequency
stabilization
of the main deflector dish...
Laddie, you need
to phase-lock
the warp fields
within three percent,
or they'll
become unstable.
What?
Well, look.
Here's the warp...
( loud beeping )
We use a multiphase
auto-containment
field now.
It's meant to operate
above three percent.
Oh, well...
that would
make the difference.
BARTEL:
We can restart the engines
in ten minutes, Commander.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
I remember a time
when the old Enterprise was
spiraling toward Psi 2000.
Yeah. Thank you.
And the captain wanted
to try a cold start
of the warp engines,
and I told him that without
a proper phase-lock,
it would take
at least 30 minutes.
"You cannot change the laws
of physics," I told him,
but he wouldn't believe me,
so I had to come up
with a whole new engine
start-up routine.
Do you know that your dilithium
crystals are going to fracture?
We re-composite
the crystals
while they're still inside
the articulation frame.
Look, Mr. Scott, I'd love
to explain everything to you,
but the captain wants
this spectrographic analysis
done by 1300 hours.
Do you mind
a little advice?
Starfleet captains
are like children.
They want everything right now,
and they want it their way,
but the secret is
to give them
only what they need,
not what they want.
Yeah, well,
I told the captain I'd have
this analysis done
in an hour.
How long would it really take?
An hour.
Oh, you didn't
tell him how long
it would really take,
did you?
Well, of course I did.
Oh, laddie,
you've got a lot to learn
if you want people to think
of you as a miracle worker.
Now, listen...
Captain Scott...
I've tried to be patient,
I've tried to be polite,
but I've got a job
to do here,
and, quite frankly,
you're in the way.
I was driving starships
while your great-grandfather
was still in diapers!
I'd think you'd be a little
grateful for some help.
( sighs )
I'll leave you to work,
Mr. La Forge.
May I help you, sir?
Aye, lad.
Scotch. Neat.
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
What in blazes is this?!
Didn't you order scotch?
Laddie,
I was drinking scotch
a hundred years
before you were born,
and I can tell you
that whatever this is,
it is definitely
not scotch.
I believe I may be
of some assistance.
Captain Scott is unaware
of the existence of synthehol.
Sy-synthehol?
Yes, sir.
It is an alcohol substitute
now being served
aboard starships.
It simulates the appearance,
taste, and smell of alcohol,
but the intoxicating effects
can be easily dismissed.
You're not quite, uh...
human, are you?
No, sir.
I am an android.
Lieutenant Commander Data.
( sighs )
Synthetic scotch,
synthetic commanders.
I believe Guinan does
keep a limited supply
of non-syntheholic products.
Perhaps one of them
would be to your liking.
What is it?
It is...
it is...
it is green.
Ahh!
COMPUTER:
Please enter program.
The android at the bar
said you could show me
my old ship.
Let me see it.
COMPUTER:
Insufficient data.
Please specify parameters.
The Enterprise.
Show me the Bridge
of the Enterprise,
you chattering piece of...
COMPUTER: There have been five
Federation ships with that name.
Please specify
by registry number.
NCC-1701.
No bloody "A," "B,"
"C," or "D."
COMPUTER: Program complete.
Enter when ready.
Here's to you, lads.
( doors open )
( sighs )
PICARD:
I hope I'm not interrupting.
I was just coming off duty,
and I wanted to see
how you were doing.
Oh, not at all,
not at all.
Would you have a drink
with me, Captain?
Thank you.
I don't know
what it is, exactly,
but I would be
real careful.
It's real...
Aldebaran whiskey.
Who do you think
gave it to Guinan?
Ah.
Constitution-class.
Aye.
You're familiar with them?
There's one in
the Fleet Museum, but...
but then, of course,
this is your Enterprise.
I actually served on two.
This was the first.
She was also the first ship
I ever served on
as Chief Engineer.
You know, I served
aboard 11 ships--
freighters, cruisers,
starships...
but this is the only one
I think of,
the only one I miss.
The first vessel
that I served on as captain
was called the Stargazer.
It was an overworked,
underpowered vessel,
always on the verge
of flying apart at the seams.
In every
measurable sense,
my Enterprise is
far superior,
but there are times,
when I would give
almost anything
to command
the Stargazer again.
It's like the first time
you fall in love.
You don't ever love a woman
quite like that again.
( sighing )
Well...
to the Enterprise
and the Stargazer--
old girlfriends
we'll never meet again.
What do you think
of the Enterprise-D?
She's a beauty,
with a good crew.
But?
But...
when I was here,
I could tell you the speed
that we were traveling
by the feel
of the deck plates.
But on your ship...
I feel like
I'm just in the way.
Well, 75 years is
a long time.
If you would care
to study some
technical
schematics or...
I'm not 18.
I can't start out
like a raw cadet.
No...
There comes a time
when a man finds
that he can't
fall in love again.
He knows
that it's time to stop.
I don't belong on your ship.
I belong on this one.
This was my home.
This is where
I had a purpose.
But it's not real.
It's just
a computer-generated fantasy.
( sighs )
And I'm just an old man
who's trying to hide in it.
Computer,
shut this
bloody thing off.
It's time I acted my age.
( door chimes )
Come.
Mr. La Forge,
I understand
that before
the Jenolan crashed,
it had conducted an extensive
survey of the Dyson sphere.
Have we been able to access
any of those records?
We did try to download
their memory core,
but it was pretty heavily
damaged in the crash.
We actually haven't been able
to get much out of it.
Perhaps Captain Scott
could be of use
in accessing
that material.
It's possible.
He does know those systems
better than any of us.
I'll have Lieutenant Bartel
beam down with him.
Mr. La Forge...
I would like you to
accompany Captain Scott.
Me, sir?
Yes.
Look, this is not an order.
It's a request,
and it's one that
you must feel
perfectly free to decline.
You see, one of
the most important things
in a person's life
is to feel useful.
Now, Mr. Scott is
a Starfleet Officer,
and I would like him
to feel useful again.
I'll go with him, sir.
Thank you.
Commander, I believe I have
found something on the sphere
which could be
a communications device.
There is an antenna array
approximately 400,000
kilometers south
of our present position.
It is emitting low-intensity
subspace signals.
Can you open a channel?
No, sir, not from
our present orbit.
The array is currently
directed away from us.
Ensign, prepare to put us in
orbit above those coordinates.
Captain Picard
to the Bridge, please.
Are you feeling
all right?
Well, never get drunk
unless you're willing
to pay for it
the next day.
I'll manage.
Okay.
Energize.
DATA: Sensors indicate
that the large circle
is a portal or airlock
possibly leading to
the interior of the sphere.
This looks like
the front door.
Should we ring the bell?
Mr. Worf,
open a channel
to that communications array.
Aye, sir.
( alarm wailing )
Some kind of tractor beam
has locked onto us.
Helm, get us out of here.
We've lost main power.
Auxiliary power
down to 20%.
We are being pulled inside.
RAGER:
Auxiliary power failing.
The resonance frequency
of the tractor beams
is incompatible
with our power systems.
Warp and impulse engine relays
have been overloaded.
I am attempting
to compensate.
RAGER: The tractor beams
have released us, sir.
Hold position here
until we can get our bearing.
Full sensor sweep, Mr. Data.
Where are we?
Approximately
90 million kilometers
from the star's photosphere.
I am reading a great deal
of surface instability.
It may be...
RAGER: Sir!
The inertial motion
from the tractor beams
is still
carrying us forward.
Impulse engines are off-line
and I can't stop our momentum.
We're falling directly
into the star.
The primary computer database
should be online now.
Give it a try.
Okay.
I've got three access lines
to the central core.
Still nothing.
Bunch of old,
useless garbage.
Huh?
I say it's old,
Mr. La Forge.
It can't handle the interface
of your power converter.
This equipment was designed
for a different era.
( sighs )
Now it's just
a piece of junk.
Well, I don't know,
it seems like
some of it's
held together pretty well.
Century out of date.
It's just... obsolete.
Well, you know,
that's interesting because...
I was just thinking
that a lot of these systems
haven't changed much
in the last 75 years.
This transporter is
basically the same system
we use on
the Enterprise.
Subspace radio
and sensors
still operate under
the same basic principle.
Impulse engine design
hasn't changed much in
the last 200 years.
If it wasn't for all
the structural damage,
this ship still might be
in service today.
Maybe so...
But when they can build ships
like your Enterprise,
who'd want to pilot
an old bucket like this?
I don't know.
If this ship were operational,
I'd bet she'd run circles
around the Enterprise
at impulse speeds.
Just because something's old,
doesn't mean you throw it away.
You know, we used to have
something called a dynamic
mode converter.
You wouldn't have something
like that on your Enterprise,
would you?
I haven't seen anything
like that in a long time,
but I bet I might be able to
come up with something similar.
La Forge to Enterprise.
Come in, please.
Interference?
No, they're gone.
DATA:
We will enter the sun's
photosphere in three minutes.
PICARD:
Maneuvering thrusters.
I've got 30% power.
It won't be enough to stop us.
No, but it may be enough
to turn us into orbit
and hold our distance
from the photosphere.
Ensign, port thrusters
ahead full.
Starboard thrusters,
back full.
DATA:
Our flight path is changing.
Right 10.7 degrees, sir--
insufficient to clear
the photosphere.
RIKER:
Lieutenant Bartel,
divert all power from
the auxiliary relay systems
to the maneuvering thrusters.
BARTEL: Aye, sir.
RAGER:
We're in orbit, Captain.
Our altitude
is 150,000 kilometers.
I'll see about getting
main power back online.
Very well.
Mr. Data, begin a scan
of the interior surface
for life-forms.
I want to know
who brought us in here...
and why.
Aye, sir.
Can't find them
anywhere in orbit.
Well, they could have
crashed into the sphere
like the Jenolan.
No, we'd be picking up
background radiation
if they'd gone down.
There's another
possibility.
They could be
inside the sphere.
Maybe.
Whatever happened,
we've got to find them.
You know, if we could get
these engines back online,
we could track them with
their impulse ion trail.
Are you daft?!
The main drive
assembly is shot,
the inducers
have melted,
the power couplings
are wrecked.
We'd need a week
just to get started,
but we don't
have a week,
so we've no sense
in crying about it.
Come on, we'll see what we can
do with your power converter.
The sphere appears
to be abandoned, Captain.
Sensors show that the star
is extremely unstable.
It is experiencing
severe bursts
of radiation
and matter expulsions.
Then that would explain
why they abandoned it,
but if there's no one
still living there,
how were
we brought inside?
I believe we have
triggered a series
of automatic piloting beams
designed to guide ships
into the sphere.
Sir, sensors show a large
magnetic disturbance
on the star's surface.
It is a solar flare,
Captain.
Magnitude: 12.
Class: B.
Shields?
Shields are up,
but only at 23%.
The star has entered
a period of increased activity.
Sensors indicate that the solar
flares will continue to grow.
In three hours,
our shields will no longer
be sufficient
to protect us, sir.
SCOTTY: Shunt the deuterium
from the main cryo-pump
to the auxiliary tank.
LA FORGE: The tank can't
withstand that kind of pressure.
( Scotty laughs )
Where'd you...
where'd you get that idea?
What do you mean,
where did I get that idea?
It's in the impulse engine
specifications.
Regulation 42/15--
"pressure variances
on the IRC tank storage"?
Yeah.
Forget it.
I wrote it.
A good engineer
is always a wee bit
conservative, at least on paper.
Just bypass the secondary
cutoff valve and boost the flow.
It'll work.
Okay.
If we've done
our jobs properly,
the engines should be
coming back online
about... now.
( engines powering up )
Hey, you were right.
The auxiliary tank
is holding.
Take the Bridge,
Commander.
Oh, no.
You're the senior
officer here.
Oh, I may be captain by rank,
but I never wanted to be
anything else
but an engineer.
All right.
WORF:
Shields still holding, sir,
but they are down
another 15%.
Mr. Worf, can we use the phasers
to open a hole in the sphere?
No, sir, the exterior shell is
composed of carbon-neutronium.
Our weapons would
be ineffective.
Mr. Data, we have to find
some way out of here.
Begin scanning for
another hatch or portal
that might
still be open.
The interior surface area
is over ten to
the 16th square kilometers.
It will take seven hours
to completely scan
the surface, sir.
( thunderous rumbling )
I will endeavor
to speed up the process, sir.
The Enterprise's ion trail
leads right to this point.
LA FORGE: It looks like
some kind of doorway.
I bet you two
bottles of scotch
that they're
inside the sphere,
and that they went in
right through that hatch.
No bet here.
The question... is how?
Look at the momentum
distribution of the ions.
It would take
an impulse engine
full reverse to put out
a signature like that.
So they didn't
go in willingly.
This looks like some kind
of communications array.
Aye.
We found hundreds of them
when we did our initial
survey 75 years ago.
Did you try hailing them?
Aye, that was standard
procedure at the time.
And we did it
right before we crashed.
Yeah.
Hailing is standard
procedure today, too.
Scotty...
what if...
those aren't
communications arrays?
What if they're
access terminals
which are triggered by
subspace signals
on certain frequencies?
Frequencies like our
standard ship's hail.
Exactly.
The Enterprise, when
they saw that terminal,
they probably did
the same thing you did
75 years ago--
open a channel--
only this time,
they triggered something
that activated
that hatch
and pulled the ship
inside the sphere.
A very nice piece
of reasoning, laddie.
Nice, indeed.
Yeah.
Well, we could probably
trigger the hatch ourselves,
only we'd get pulled in
just like they were.
Maybe all we need to do is
to get our foot in the door.
Now, we might not
be pulled inside
when the hatch opens...
if we keep our distance
from the sphere,
say, uh...
half-a-million kilometers.
Then, when the hatch
starts to close,
we move in,
and we use the Jenolan
to jam the hatch open,
hoping that the Enterprise
will escape.
You can't be serious.
That hatch is huge.
It'll crush this ship
like an egg.
Geordi, the shields will hold,
don't worry about that.
And I can get a few extra
gigawatts out of these babies.
Oh, Scotty, it's crazy.
Geordi, I have spent
my whole life
trying to figure out
crazy ways of doing things.
I'm telling you,
as one engineer to another,
I can do this.
( sighs )
All right.
Let's do it.
Aye.
We're at
500,000 kilometers.
Engines are ready.
Okay.
Here we go.
Come on.
There's nothing out here.
Give it up.
That's it.
Let's go.
Full impulse.
( console beeping )
Sir, there is an audio message
from Commander La Forge.
La Forge to Enterprise.
Do you read me?
Go ahead, Commander,
we read you.
We're using the Jenolan
to hold open the hatch
that you came through,
but our shields
aren't going to
hold out much longer.
Understood.
Ensign, set a course.
The plasma
intercooler is gone.
The engines
are overheating.
I've lost helm control.
La Forge to Enterprise.
Captain, we're not going
to be able to move this ship
out of the way
when you get here.
You're going to have to destroy
it in order to escape.
How much longer
before we reach them?
With impulse engines
operating at 60% power,
it will take one minute,
forty seconds.
Bridge to
Transporter Room three.
Prepare to beam two
from the Jenolan
as soon as we're within range.
It's coming apart, lad.
I can't do
anything else.
Photon torpedoes
armed and ready, sir.
We are within
transporter range.
Bridge to Transporter Room.
Energize.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
Fire torpedoes.
There, now, that
wasn't so bad, was it?
( chuckles )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46125.3:
Starfleet has dispatched
two science vessels
to study the Dyson sphere
while we proceed
to Starbase 55.
So this alien space baby--
which was about the size
of a four-story building--
really thought the Enterprise
was its mother.
Oh, you're pulling
an old man's leg.
No, really.
It was suckling power directly
from the ship's fusion reactors,
so Dr. Brahms and I
changed the power frequency
from 21 centimeters
to .02 centimeters.
So you soured
the milk!
That's right.
Oh, enjoy these
times, Geordi.
You're the Chief
Engineer of a starship
and it's a time of your life
that'll never come again.
When it's gone,
it's gone.
Now, lad, I thought
you were going to buy me
a drink in Ten Forward.
Actually,
I had a better idea.
You're giving me
one of your shuttles?
Well, call it
an extended loan.
Since you lost your ship saving
ours, it seemed only fair.
She's not much
to look at.
Laddie, every woman
has her own charm.
You just have to know
where to look for it.
Well, she's a little slow,
but she'll certainly get you
to the Norpin colony,
if that's really
where you want to go.
The Norpin colony is
for old men to retire.
Maybe someday
I'll end up there,
but not yet.
Well, bon voyage,
Mr. Scott.
Thank you, sir,
for everything.
Mr. Scott.
Good-bye.
Bye-bye.
Scotty.
Thank you.
Bye. Be well.
A good crew.
Yeah, they are.
And a fine ship,
a credit to her name,
but I've always found
that a ship is only as good
as the engineer
who takes care of her.
And from what I can see,
the Enterprise
is in good hands.
You take care
of yourself out there.
Aye.