Captain's Log,
Stardate 46154.2.
The Enterprise has entered
the Amargosa Diaspora,
an unusually dense
globular cluster.
We are faced
with the daunting task
of charting this vast region.
( sighs )
( beeping )
Lieutenant Shipley,
let's get a triangulation
on these sector points.
Aye, sir.
( sighs )
I'm sorry I'm late.
I overslept again.
What have we got?
Well, the cluster's
a lot more dense
than we thought.
It's going to take
three days just to
map out one-tenth of it.
Three days?
I think we found a way
to speed that up a bit.
We've been testing a way
to channel warp energy
directly to
the main deflector grid.
It should enhance
the long-range sensors.
The modification
would increase our
sensory efficiency
and imaging resolution
by 25% or more.
That sounds like
that'll use up a
lot of warp energy.
Well, we'd channel it
through the EPS mains
on Deck Four,
near Cargo Bay Four.
Okay,
let's give it a try.
Data, let's get those
field taps on-line.
Commander, I would
like to remind you
about my poetry reading
this afternoon.
I wouldn't miss it
for the world.
I can't wait to see
what he's come up with.
DATA:
"Then we sat on the sand
for some time and observed
"how the oceans that cover
the world were perturbed
"by the tides from
the orbiting moon overhead.
"'How relaxing the sound
of the waves is,' you said.
"I began to expound
upon tidal effects
"when you asked me to stop,
looking somewhat perplexed.
"So I did not explain
why the sunset turns red
and we watched
the occurrence...
in silence... instead."
That poem was written
in anapestic tetrameter.
For my ninth poem...
I don't understand.
I can barely keep
my eyes open.
DATA:
Throughout the ages,
from Keats to Jorkemo,
poets have composed
odes to individuals
who have had a profound
effect upon their lives.
In keeping
with that tradition,
I have written my next
poem in honor of my cat.
I call it "Ode to Spot."
"Felis Catus is your
taxonomic nomenclature,
"an endothermic quadruped,
carnivorous by nature,
"your visual, olfactory,
and auditory senses
"contribute to your hunting
skills and natural defenses.
"I find myself intrigued
by your subvocal oscillations,
"a singular development
of cat communications
"that obviates your basic
hedonistic predilection
"for a rhythmic
stroking of your fur
to demonstrate affection.
"A tail is quite essential
for your acrobatic talents.
"You would not be
so agile if you lacked
its counterbalance.
"And when not being utilized
to aid in locomotion,
"it often serves
to illustrate the state
of your emotion..."
Commander, you have
anticipated my denouement.
However, the sentiment
is appreciated.
I will continue.
"Oh, Spot,
the complex levels
of behavior you display
"connote a fairly
well-developed
cognitive array.
"And though you are
not sentient, Spot,
and do not comprehend,
I, nonetheless,
consider you a true
and valued friend."
( snoring )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I have no problem
getting to sleep
and then I think
I'm sleeping all night.
When I wake up,
I feel exhausted.
How long has this
been going on?
Two, three days.
Do you have to hold
that thing that close?
I'm sorry.
I've been on edge
all day.
Well...
other than some muscle
tension in your neck,
I don't see anything
physically wrong with you.
Have you been
having bad dreams?
Not that I can remember.
This could be the result
of lack of REM sleep.
What do you recommend?
Drink this before
going to bed.
What is it?
A recipe for
a warm milk toddy.
A hot milk toddy?
You're kidding.
The heat activates the
amino acids in the lactose,
making it a natural sedative.
Besides, it's a recipe of
the captain's Aunt Adele.
It's delicious.
Well, at this point,
I'll try anything.
And listen, if it still
bothers you tomorrow,
come and see me, and
I'll run further tests.
Thanks.
Everything's in place.
Warp grid couplers,
subspace field taps...
All right, let's do it.
Lieutenant Shipley,
initiate warp power transfer.
Aye, sir.
Verifying sensor
calibration.
EPS mains holding stable.
Sensor array on-line.
Come on, work.
Geordi?
Active scanner output
has increased by 26%.
Inform astrophysics
that the new La Forge
sensor array is on-line
and awaiting major
scientific discoveries.
Yes, sir.
Geordi... may I make
a personal inquiry?
It concerns my
poetry reading.
Sure, Data, what is it?
I noticed
that many spectators
seemed distracted
during my presentation.
Was my poetry
uninteresting?
( clears throat )
Well, it was...
very well-constructed--
a virtual tribute to form.
Thank you.
And?
And what?
Did it evoke
an emotional response?
( sighs )
Well...
Your hesitation suggests
you are trying to
protect my feelings.
However, since I
have none, I would
prefer you to be honest.
An artist's growth depends
upon accurate feedback.
Well, your-- your poems
were... clever, Data.
And-- and your haiku
was clever.
And your sonnet was...
clever.
But did it evoke
an emotional response?
Ah, to be honest,
no, I don't think so.
Hmm.
Then I did not succeed
in my efforts.
No, it's not that
you didn't succeed.
You accomplished
a lot, but...
if you want to
touch people,
don't concentrate so
much on rhyme and meter.
Think more about
what you want to say
instead of how
you're saying it.
( alarm beeping )
It's the power grid
warning.
I am reading
a massive EPS explosion.
Where?
I am attempting
to localize it.
It is Cargo Bay Four.
I've got three people
in there.
Damage control, medical
team to Cargo Bay Four.
Let's go.
The field imbalance
has subsided.
There may still be
a residual discharge.
Stand clear.
( indistinct voices )
Is there something
wrong, sir?
And there's no evidence
of an EPS explosion.
The sensors seemed
to think there was.
I think my modification
to the sensor array
may have caused a pattern
recognition failure.
Just a sensor glitch?
That's my guess.
( sighs )
Let's perform a
level-3 diagnostic
on the internal sensor
network and make sure
that we haven't
overlooked anything.
Aye, sir.
And could we pick this up
in the morning, Geordi?
Get a fresh start?
Would you do me a favor?
Stop by my quarters,
0700 hours.
I'm having trouble
waking up.
Sure, Commander.
Good night.
( sighs )
( grunts )
Commander.
Gordon.
Who is it?
It's La Forge.
Come in.
Good morning.
Morning?
I just went to bed.
Commander,
it's 0700 hours.
And so she said,
"if they're not squirming,
we won't eat 'em."
( laughing )
Ah, Mr. Worf,
my good Klingon.
Sir, welcome.
What a pleasure it is
to have you back
with us again so soon.
So, Lieutenant,
a haircut today?
Trim your beard?
I would like
my hair trimmed.
Ah, a trim.
Of course.
Not like last time.
Oh, no. Just
a little off the top.
I took way too much
off last time.
Um, I was just telling
my colleague, Mr. Setti,
how thick and luxuriant
Klingon hair is.
It's such
a pleasure to cut,
sometimes I
get carried away.
You know, all those
away missions--
wind and-- and dry air.
The elements really
are harsh on the hair.
I'd like to suggest
that you start using
a conditioning agent.
I... I promise...
not too much off the top.
Just before
the grid alarm sounded,
we were running warp power
through this junction.
Somehow, it must have tripped
the internal scanners.
And it showed up as
an EPS explosion?
Yes, but
the question is, why?
I've made modifications
to the sensors before,
but nothing like this
has ever happened.
Well, we can't waste our
time chasing sensor ghosts.
We should probably keep
the whole array off-line
until you can get
a closer look.
( yawning )
Oh, excuse me.
I know the feeling.
The past few nights,
it seems like
as soon as my head
hits the pillow,
it's time to get up
in the morning.
I'm sure we could all use
a little shore leave
once this survey
is completed.
Definitely.
Keep me posted?
Yeah. Data?
I'm wondering if you
could give me a hand.
I need to run a structural
integrity scan.
I want to make sure that
none of the conduit was...
Ooh...
What is it?
( sighs )
This is
the second time today
that my visor has just
cut out like that.
Are you all
right, Geordi?
I don't know.
I just got
a very weird feeling.
Maybe I should go
to sick bay.
I will run the
integrity scan.
Thanks, Data.
CRUSHER:
This is curious.
There's a slight
bacterial infection
around your neural inputs.
It was probably
interrupting
the data stream.
An infection?
What from?
It doesn't match
any bacterial
strains on record.
I'm going to have to
sterilize the area,
but I need to run a
resonance tissue scan
to search for any signs
of additional infection.
Come over here.
Sit down.
Now, come forward.
Now, you're going to
need to hold very still.
How's the scan
going, Data?
I have just
started the scan.
Did you not go
to sick bay?
Data, I've been there
for over an hour and a half.
That is not possible.
My internal chronometer
indicates you have been gone
for exactly
one minute, 15 seconds.
Well, I'm
telling you, Data,
I've been gone
for over an hour.
Computer, what is
the time, please?
The time is 14:27 hours.
You are correct.
90 minutes, 17 seconds
have passed since
you left the room.
What have you been doing
all this time?
I have no memory of events
during that period.
When we have finished
here, I will perform
a self-diagnostic.
You know, first we
picked up a false
EPS explosion,
then my visor cuts out twice
and now, you lose an hour,
all in this cargo bay.
La Forge to engineering.
I want a diagnostic team to
Cargo Bay Four immediately.
On our way, sir.
Ensign Rager, cartography
needs a better position
to study cluster FGC-13.
Bring us about,
heading 123 mark four.
Aye, sir.
Helm won't lock to
those coordinates, sir.
First time navigating
through a globular
cluster, Ensign?
You have to compensate
for the gravimetric
interference before...
Is there something
wrong, sir?
No.
I don't know.
Put us back on our
original heading, Ensign.
Don't tell me...
This can't be right.
Data...
come here and take a
look at this, would you?
I think we have
another sensor glitch.
Sensors are
functioning normally.
They are detecting a
subspace particle emission
originating
from within this room.
From within this room?
That's impossible.
The emission is emanating
from this direction.
Geordi...
DATA:
the structure
of the bulkhead
has been altered
on a subatomic level.
The metal itself
is in a state of
quasi-molecular flux.
What's causing it?
Well, this is where it
gets a little wild, Captain.
Behind that panel
is a junction
that we were using
to transfer warp power
to the sensor array.
We're reading a
subspace particle stream
emanating from
that junction.
It appears to be composed
of spatially inverted
tetryon particles.
We believe they
are emanating
from a tertiary
subspace manifold.
But I thought that
tetryons were unstable
in normal space.
We don't understand it
either, sir.
Something from
that deep in subspace
shouldn't be able to
exist in our universe,
but there it is.
Does it pose a danger
to the ship?
Not unless it spreads.
If it does, we can beam
the bulkhead into space
and erect a force field
in its place.
Well, keep
that option ready.
In the meantime,
proceed with the analysis.
Aye, sir.
When I sat at the console,
it triggered a response
like I'd been trapped.
I had to get
out of there.
Was it something about
the console itself?
No. I felt like
I was disconnected,
like it was something
that I had dreamed.
You're the third person
who's come to me today
with something like this--
an intense emotional
response provoked by
an object.
Did any of them
know why they had
had the response?
No. They couldn't
explain it any more
than you could.
You know, at this point
I'm not willing to say
it's coincidence.
Maybe we should all
get together.
Well, talking about it
would help you
understand your response.
( sighs )
I'm going to find out
if anyone else on the ship
has had these kind
of experiences.
Will, you told me you
had an unusual experience
when you sat down
at the console.
Why don't you
describe it?
It was vague, the way
you recall a dream.
I remember
the sensation
of feeling trapped
and something about
a-- a smooth surface.
I had a similar response,
but to a pair of scissors.
Have you dreamt
about scissors recently?
I may have. I have
no distinct memory of it.
When my visor cut out
in the cargo bay, I had
a weird feeling, too.
It was something
about a smooth surface.
It was smooth...
and cold.
Yeah, it was cold.
Yes. Cold.
It was... elevated?
A platform.
Right.
Like a bench.
Or a table.
It seems you've all had
a similar experience.
Is there anything
else you remember
besides a table?
( sighs )
Maybe there's a way
we can all help ourselves
to remember more.
TROI:
Well, you all
remember a table,
so let's start with that.
Computer,
show me a table.
There are 5,047
classifications
of tables on file.
Specify
design parameters.
Can you be more specific
about the table?
You mentioned it
was smooth and cold.
Can you remember
what shape it was?
Long.
It was long.
Yeah, and it had
a rectangular shape.
Computer, show me
a rectangular
conference table.
It's too high.
Computer, reduce the height
of the table by 25%.
No. The table was smaller
and it was inclined.
Computer, decrease the
table's surface area by 20%
and incline
the top 15 degrees.
No. It wasn't
made of wood.
It was smoother,
more metallic.
Computer, make this
a metal table.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's starting
to look right.
Was there anything else
in the room?
Furniture?
Chairs? A door?
Other people?
No.
It was dark.
RIKER:
Yes, it was dark.
You couldn't see
beyond the table.
Computer, lower the
surrounding light level.
LA FORGE:
There was a light
right in my face--
a bright light.
Computer, give me
a bright light right
above the table.
Specify light source.
I couldn't tell.
I-- it was above me.
An overhead lamp.
Estimated distance
of light source?
I don't know.
It was at least two
or three meters above.
Brighter.
You said you were uneasy
when you sat down
at the conn position.
Yes. I felt trapped
by the console.
But it wasn't like this.
There was
something else here.
A restraint of some kind?
Yes, there was
a restraint.
It was flat, metal.
It was made of metal.
It came down over my legs.
No, no, it... no.
It was... it was
across my chest.
It was right here.
It was holding you down?
Yes. It was part
of the table.
It was here.
It was right here.
Computer, create
a restraining arm
attached to the
right side of the
table at the midpoint.
TROI:
Was it like that?
Computer, put controls
on the restraining arm,
a control panel,
lights.
WOMAN:
There was something
else there,
over the head
of the table.
A metal swing arm.
Computer, create
a metal swing arm,
double-jointed,
total length one meter.
Connect it
to the head of the table.
WORF:
There was something
attached to it--
a tool of some sort.
Scissor-like.
Computer, produce
a pair of scissors
attached to the armature.
The handle is wrong.
It was not scissors.
Computer, make the handle
a single-piece grip
ten centimeters long,
solid metal.
Now make one blade longer,
curved inward...
and give the other blade
a jagged edge.
TROI:
All right.
You were lying
on the table.
You had a bright light
shining in your eyes.
Were there any smells
in the room?
Were there any sounds?
Yes. Yes,
there was a sound.
( sighs )
Computer, there were noises
coming from the darkness.
Strange...
like whispering.
( low whispering )
More like clicks.
Clicking sounds.
( clicking )
Louder.
( louder clicking )
RIKER:
Faster.
( faster clicking )
RIKER:
More of them.
I've been in
this room before.
We've all been here
before.
CRUSHER:
Here it is again.
Something has caused
high levels of serotonin
to be produced in
Geordi's visual cortex.
When I examined
him earlier today,
I thought it was the result
of a bacterial infection,
but now I'm finding the
same thing in all three.
They all have elevated
levels of serotonin.
It's concentrated
in the hippocampus,
which suggests that
they've been exposed
to a neuro-sedative.
And that's not all.
I have detected
minute tetryon
particle traces in
their subdermal tissues.
Tetryons?
Like the emissions
in the cargo bay.
I have completed
my self-diagnostic
and have confirmed
that I was not aboard
the Enterprise
for 90 minutes, 17 seconds
yesterday afternoon.
Are you sure?
Whenever I am
on the ship,
the warp field leaves
an electromagnetic signal
on my internal
servo fluid system.
Between the period
of 1254 to 1426 hours,
that signature is missing.
Computer, are there
any members of the crew
of the Enterprise missing?
There are two crew members
unaccounted for.
PICARD:
Identify them.
Lieutenant Edward Hagler
and Ensign Sariel Rager.
When did they leave?
They have not been present
since 23:32 hours.
PICARD:
How did they leave?
Method of departure
unknown.
Picard to bridge.
Bridge here, Captain.
Raise shields.
And I want a level-4
security alert.
I need to know if anyone
comes on or off this ship.
Aye, sir.
Mr. La Forge, Mr. Data,
I believe that if we find
the source of those
tetryon emissions,
we'll find the
missing crew members.
We're on it, sir.
Dr. Crusher?
My God!
What is it?
It looks as though your
arm has been severed
and then reattached.
What?!
The skeletal structure
in your radius and ulna
is offset by .02 microns.
Your arm has been amputated
and surgically reattached.
Any progress with
the analysis, Lieutenant?
Look at this.
Data, the tetryon emissions
have intensified.
They seem to be focusing
in this direction...
coalescing here.
They're reading as a
point of subspace energy.
It appears to be
the beginnings of
a spatial rupture.
Yeah, the tetryon
emissions are modulating
in a way that...
that looks like
somebody is
controlling the energy.
You know...
the signals from the
modifications I made
to the sensor array--
some of them dipped
pretty deep into subspace.
Maybe they caught
somebody's attention.
At the rate the
rupture is expanding,
we will soon be in
danger of hull breach.
Maybe we should try
surrounding it
with a subspace
containment field.
Other than the
tetryon emissions
in Cargo Bay Four,
our internal sensors
haven't recorded
anything unusual in
the past three days.
Initiate a metallurgical
analysis of the ship's hull.
Subspace field incursions
may have left a trace.
Captain, sensors indicate
that Lieutenant Hagler
has returned to
the Enterprise.
He is in his quarters--
Deck Nine, Section 17.
Computer, emergency entry,
Chief Medical Officer
Beverly Crusher.
( wheezing )
Crusher to sick bay.
Get me a plasma
infusion unit to
Deck Nine, Section 19.
His blood is turning
into a liquid polymer.
( groans softly )
We've set up a containment
field in Cargo Bay Four
but the rupture
just keeps expanding.
I'd say we've got another
five to six hours before
it breaches the hull.
Can we still beam
the affected sections
out into space?
No, sir.
The spatial rupture
is creating severe
nucleonic interference.
It is impossible to
obtain a positive lock
on the bulkheads.
Has your analysis suggested
any way in which we might
seal this rupture?
LA FORGE:
We think we can close
the rupture
by neutralizing
the tetryon emissions
with a coherent
graviton pulse,
but we'd have to do
that at the source.
How do we find
the source?
Good question.
The emissions are
coming from a tertiary
subspace domain
but subspace has an
infinite number of domains.
It's like a huge
honeycomb with an
infinite number of cells.
We need to isolate
the exact cell
that these emissions
are coming from.
If someone homed onto
the subspace signals
created by our
modified signal array,
could we do the same
to them?
Track the tetryon emissions
to their universe?
Tetryon particles
have a random momentum.
Our sensors
cannot track them, sir.
Perhaps we could construct
a homing device--
something that our sensors
could track.
It's a good idea,
but there's no way
to get that device
to the source.
Yes, there is.
Give it to me.
They've taken me for
the last few nights.
And if I'm right,
the same thing
will happen tonight.
Well, if you had
a homing device,
we could track it
to your location
in subspace.
Then as soon as they
send you back to the ship,
we could transmit
the graviton pulse
and neutralize
the tetryon emissions.
If they send him back.
Ensign Rager still
hasn't been returned.
They're going to
take me whether I
want to go or not.
Well, we could wait
as long as possible
for you to be returned,
Number One.
But when the spatial
ruptures begin to
threaten the ship,
then we would
have to transmit
that graviton pulse.
Understood.
Perhaps there's...
a way that we could
give you an advantage.
A way of keeping
you conscious after
they've taken you.
Doctor, can you develop
some counteragent
to the neuro-sedative
that they have been
giving the crew?
I could give you
a neuro-stimulant,
but the dosage would
have to be rather high
to counteract the effects.
It could be risky.
I'm willing to take
that risk.
Make it so.
Mr. La Forge, begin work
on that homing device.
This should ward off
their neuro-sedative
for about 12 hours.
I hope it's enough.
It's going to
have to be.
I can't risk giving
you a higher dosage.
I've locked this tricorder
into a continuous cycle.
That way, it'll keep
recording, whether
you open it or not.
Hopefully,
you can bring back
some information
about their domain.
We've modified a sensor
relay emitter to transmit
a subspace beacon.
When this indicator
lights up,
it means that we've
locked onto your location.
Understood.
( clicking )
( sighs )
( humming whoosh )
Captain, Commander
Riker has been taken
from the Enterprise.
( multiple, rapid clicks )
( clicking continues )
Mr. La Forge, report.
I still can't locate
the homing signal.
We've covered the entire
upper-subspace energy band.
We're extending the scan
to adjacent levels.
Mr. Data, your status?
The rupture has
expanded another 4.2%.
Without further reinforcement,
containment field integrity
will fail in
approximately 14 minutes.
Can you divert more power
to the containment field?
I can try
to augment the field
with auxiliary power,
but it won't be much.
Make it so.
Aye, sir.
( clicking )
( clicking continues )
Captain, I've located
the homing signal.
Locking onto it now.
It's coming from a subspace
energy level of 16.2 KEV.
Stand by to initiate
the graviton pulse.
Graviton emitter's
at full power, sir.
Standing by.
Mr. Data, how much time?
At the present rate,
containment failure
will occur in
approximately nine minutes.
( clicking )
Captain, the
containment field is
beginning to fluctuate.
Failure anticipated
in three minutes,
11 seconds.
We can't afford to
wait any longer.
Begin the graviton pulse.
Initiating pulse now.
( rapid, intense clicking )
Data to engineering.
The graviton pulse
is having an effect.
Tetryon emissions
have decreased by 19%.
Captain, additional
subharmonics have appeared.
They are reinforcing
the tetryon emissions.
They appear to
be counteracting
the graviton pulse.
The rupture is beginning
to expand again, sir.
It looks like somebody
is fighting back.
Can you strengthen
the graviton pulse?
I can try to set up
a random frequency shift.
If we can keep them
from guessing our
pulse modulation,
they might not be
able to compensate.
( clicking )
Tetryon emissions
continue to increase.
The rupture
is still expanding.
Hull breach is imminent.
They're reacting
faster than we can
shift frequencies.
Shipley,
program the emitters
for full-spectrum
pulse compression.
I want to channel all
of the graviton energy
into a single burst.
Let's see if they
can handle that.
Ready, Commander.
( clicking )
( rapid clicking )
The rupture is
beginning to close, sir.
Recharge the emitters.
Let's hit them again.
Come on.
Ready.
DATA:
The rupture is 86% closed.
We're almost there.
One more burst
should do it.
Emitters recharging.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46191.2.
The tetryon emissions
in Cargo Bay Four have ceased
and there have been
no further indications
of alien intrusions.
All Enterprise crew members
are safe and accounted for,
but we are still left with
some unanswered questions.
Based on the
information gathered
from Commander Riker's
tricorder,
we have determined
that the molecular structure
of the alien life-forms
is solanagen-based.
We think that's why
they couldn't come through
into our space as
easily as they could
take us into theirs.
They needed to learn
how to remodulate their
cellular energy states
in order to survive
in our universe.
The tricorder readings
indicate they created
a small pocket
of our universe
in their laboratory
to keep those
they abducted alive.
Like putting a fish
in a bucket of water.
It's probably what
they were trying to do
in Cargo Bay Four--
create a pocket of
their universe in ours.
What can we do to prevent
this from happening again?
Looks like they
found us initially
by discovering my
modified sensor signal.
We should warn all
starfleet ships not
to make that same mistake.
Have we any idea
what came through
the rupture
before we were able
to shut it down?
No, sir. We were unable to track
it once it left the cargo bay.
Maybe it was a probe
of some kind.
Possibly they
were simply curious--
explorers like ourselves.
Ensign Rager and I were
lucky to have escaped.
Lieutenant Hagler's dead.
Whoever it was sent
that thing was more
than simply curious.