Captain's Log,
Stardate 46192.3.
We have arrived
at Starbase 112
and are loading
relief supplies
destined for Tagra IV,
an ecologically devastated
planet in the Argolis Cluster.
We have also taken on
a rather unusual passenger.
Welcome to the Enterprise,
Miss Rogers.
I'm delighted
to have you on board.
Thank you, sir.
And congratulations.
I understand that
you were selected
for this internship
out of hundreds
of applicants.
Yes, sir, I still can't
believe they chose me.
There were lots
of other people
with better records.
CRUSHER:
Her transcript
is very impressive.
She's done honors work
in neurobiology,
plasma dynamics,
and eco-regeneration.
I'd say that's
pretty well-rounded.
Well, that's a nice way
of saying that I
haven't decided what I'm
going to do with my life.
I've arranged to have
you work in all the
major departments
while you're here,
and I'm willing to bet
that by the time
it's over, you'll have
a pretty good idea
what field
you're interested in.
PICARD:
Or, at least
what fields you're not
interested in.
( door chimes )
Come.
We're bringing up
the rest of the cargo now.
We should be ready to leave
within the hour.
Commander, will you
escort Miss Rogers
to her quarters?
I need to discuss
the Tagrans' medical
needs with Dr. Crusher.
And Miss Rogers?
Yes?
You've won yourself
a rare opportunity.
Avail yourself of it.
I will, sir,
and thank you.
It'll take you a few
days before you know
where everything is.
If you need any help
you just use... use
one of these com panels.
Um... we're on deck
seven, section four.
You're right.
I practically
memorized the specs
on the way over here.
You're a quick study.
This is it.
Is this for me?
It's all yours.
It's so big.
For honor students,
only the best.
Well, I could have
brought my zoo.
Your zoo?
Well, it's just what
my parents call it.
Three dogs isn't
that many, is it?
It depends how
they get along.
I could have had a dozen.
Mother said
enough is enough.
I'm sure going
to miss them.
We'll keep you so busy
you won't have a chance to.
I've got to get going.
I have to get back
to Cargo Bay Two.
Well, thanks for, uh...
walking me down.
Sure.
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I didn't mean it.
Oh, no.
( puppies whining )
You guys can't stay here.
( whining )
Come on, all of you.
( puppy whining and barking )
Hello.
( puppy whining )
Oh, come here, little one.
You, too. Come on.
Come on.
( sighs )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
See all these readouts?
That's your heart rate,
your blood pressure,
all your vital signs.
You're in good shape.
You might just live
to be my age.
Now, all these tricorders
need to be tested
before they can be put
in the supply containers
that we're taking
to Tagra.
So, I should scan
myself with each one
to make sure the
readouts are working.
Any unit that doesn't,
put it aside
and we'll do a diagnostic
on it later.
Okay.
I hear you've been
accepted to the Academy.
I have a son there.
Oh. Being posted
on the Enterprise,
I guess you don't get
to see him very often.
No, not as often
as I'd like.
Do you have
any other children?
My husband died a
number of years ago.
Wes was our only child.
Was he old enough
to know his father?
Jack died when he was five.
My parents died
when I was a baby, too.
I don't remember anything
about them.
Sometimes I wonder
what they were like.
Your adoptive parents
are in Starfleet, aren't they?
Yeah, they're marine biologists.
They've just been posted
to the Bilaren system.
CREWMAN:
Sick Bay to Dr. Crusher.
You wanted to be told
when the cultures were ready.
On my way.
When you've finished
with the tricorders,
Nurse Ogawa will help you
to take them
down to Shuttle Bay
for loading.
Okay.
Oh, thank you very much
for your help.
We can use every
available hand we can get.
This is one of
the largest relief efforts
we've ever mounted.
Now, why are you bringing
everything down
in shuttlecraft?
Well, because we can't use
the transporters
for all the ionization
in the Tagran atmosphere.
From the baristatic
filters?
How did you know that?
I did a paper on
eco-regeneration.
Well, then you know
that a thousand
baristatic filters
puts out quite a bit
of ionization.
A thousand?
Yeah. They've managed
to pollute their
atmosphere pretty badly.
It's amazing to think
that they go to such lengths
to clean the air,
instead of regulating
the emissions
that cause the problem.
Yeah, you're right.
Actually, the only thing
the filters can do
is keep things
from getting worse.
They shoot the air
full of...
Commander,
are you all right?
You okay?
I didn't even
see it coming.
And this is
the main control area.
We can access any
of the primary circuits
from all of these panels.
Over here is
a Jefferies tube...
Where most of the major
conduits are routed.
You've been doing
your homework.
It's hard to imagine
how much energy is
harnessed in there.
Imagination
is not necessary.
The scale
is readily quantifiable.
We are presently generating
12.75 billion
gigawatts per...
( alarm sounding )
The temperature
in the reaction chamber
has increased by 47%.
Injector couplings are frozen.
I can't slow down the reaction.
Temperature increase
is at 106% and rising.
La Forge to Bridge.
We're looking at
a core breach.
We're going to have
to try and vent the plasma.
Plasma inductors
are not responding.
We're going to lose containment.
All right, everybody,
out of here now!
Let's go! Let's move it!
Data, bring down
the isolation door.
We're going to have to eject
the warp core.
( explosion )
Temperature in the
reaction chamber...
has returned to normal.
She's a little shaken up
but she's going
to be fine.
You said she
was adopted.
Could she be
an alien?
She's human.
There's nothing
more unusual about her.
Not that my instruments
can detect.
Commander, have you been able
to determine
the cause of the warp breach?
No, sir.
Everything was normal
and then suddenly
it's like the laws of physics
went right out the window.
Q:
And why shouldn't they?
They're so inconvenient.
Q.
Mon Capitain.
Are you responsible for this
incident in Engineering?
Of course.
I needed to find out
if what I suspected
about the girl were true.
That being?
That she's Q.
TROI:
Amanda's a Q?
How is that possible?
Her-Her parents--
her biological parents--
were human.
Well, not exactly.
They had assumed human form
in order to visit Earth,
I suppose for... for amusement,
but in vulgar human fashion,
they proceeded to conceive
a child.
And then like
mawkish humans,
they became
attached to it.
What is it about these
squirming little infants
that you find so appealing?
I'm sure that's beyond
your comprehension, Q.
I desperately hope so.
TROI:
What happened
to Amanda's parents?
They died in an accident.
None of us knew
whether she had
inherited
the capacities of the Q,
but recently,
they've begun to emerge,
and as an expert
in humanity,
I was sent to investigate.
You, an expert
in humanity?
Not a very challenging field
of study, I grant you.
Are you saying that you
created a core breach
just to test this girl?
Uh-huh.
What would have happened
if she couldn't stop it?
Then I would have known
she wasn't a Q.
And now that you know,
what do you intend to do?
Instruct her.
If this child does not learn
how to control her power,
she may accidentally
destroy herself...
or all of you,
or perhaps your entire galaxy.
I find it hard to believe
that you're here
to do us a favor.
You're quite right,
I wouldn't,
but there are those
in the Continuum
who have an over-exaggerated
sense of responsibility.
They think that we need
to take precautions
to keep the little dear
from running amok.
And once you've taught her,
then you'll go away?
And leave her here?
Of course not.
She'll come back to the
Continuum where she belongs.
Wait a minute. You can't just
come in here and take her away
from everything
she's ever known.
I assure you, I can.
She has plans for herself.
She wants to have a career
and a family.
I'm rescuing her
from that miserable existence.
That "miserable existence"
is all she's known
for the last 18 years.
You have no right
to take her away from it.
Mon Capitain, I really think
that we need to speak privately.
Well, there,
that's better.
Crusher gets more shrill
with each passing year.
Q, what is it
you really want?
Well, since you know
so much about the Q,
I thought you'd be
the perfect person
to introduce me
to the child.
Let her know that
she can trust me.
I don't trust you, Q.
Why should I expect Amanda to?
Well, she'd better,
because I'm all she's got.
She needs me to help her prepare
for her future with the Q.
But what if she doesn't want
that future?
It must be her decision.
Oh, yes! Yes! Yes!
Do you think that
she will want to remain
an enfeebled mortal?
Well, if she really is Q,
she must understand
what that means.
Very well.
I will introduce you, but...
( sighs )
we cannot argue
like this in front of her.
We must at least
appear to be...
Pals?
Civil.
I knew I could count
on you, Jean-Luc.
Mr. Data, I want
you to access
any available records
on Amanda Rogers.
Yes, Captain.
I want to know about
her biological parents...
about their death.
I find it odd that any Q
could die in an accident.
It is not consistent with
what we know of them, sir.
I'm convinced that Q isn't
telling us everything.
See what you
can find out.
Aye, sir.
It started happening
about six months ago--
things that I would wish for
would just suddenly appear.
I thought I was going crazy.
In a funny way,
finding this out
is kind of a relief.
I can understand
that.
This person
I mentioned--
from the Q Continuum--
would like to meet you
if it's all
right with you.
I'm ready.
Good.
There's my girl.
Amanda, allow me
to introduce, uh... Q.
He's, um...
he's an acquaintance of ours.
We've, uh...
we've known him for years.
Very impressive the way you
contained that explosion.
What else have you done?
I-I don't understand.
Telekinesis? Teleportation?
Spontaneous
combustion
of someone you don't like?
That sort of thing.
Amanda, what Q is asking
is have you ever deliberately
used your abilities?
Not until I came here.
The first time it happened
was when the container
almost fell on Commander Riker.
And you handled
that very well.
That's why I gave you
a greater challenge--
the warp core breach.
She has potential, this one.
I see no reason
why she can't return
to the Continuum right now.
What?
Q...
I don't want
to go anywhere.
Don't worry.
With time, you'll overcome
the disadvantages
you suffered
as a child.
No one will hold
it against you
for having been human.
Let's go.
Leave me alone!
I'm not going anywhere with you.
You agree that
she has a right to
choose her own future,
but the first chance you
get, you try to abduct her.
You're overreacting,
as usual, Picard.
I was merely
testing her powers.
She's quite a little spitfire,
now, isn't she?
What's going on, Q?
What's your real purpose here?
I think I've been
perfectly clear.
The Continuum has a vested
interest in this young woman.
If you wish to protect
that investment,
I suggest that you approach her
differently.
She was being impetuous.
She'll just have to start
behaving like a Q.
If I'm not mistaken,
she just did.
You understand, don't you?
It's just that I have
these things that I want to do.
I'm going to go
to the Academy.
I want a career
and I want to
join Starfleet.
You can still do
all those things.
Yeah, but it just seems
so complicated now.
I mean, these powers
that I have--
they're just going
to stand in the way.
I don't want to have
to deal with that.
Well, you're
going to have to.
Listen, I can only imagine
how you feel.
That certainly would be easier
if this had never happened
or if it would just go away...
but it's not going to go away,
and you need someone
to help you,
and the person
who can help you is... Q.
( sighs )
But he's so horrible.
He is the only one
who can help you
to understand who you are.
Amanda...
you are going
to have to make
some hard choices
about your future,
and you can't make them
if you're going
to ignore the truth.
Yeah. I know.
But I don't want any of this
to disrupt my time here.
I want to do everything
that I'm expected to do
and I don't want you
to treat me any differently.
Please.
You've got a deal.
The first free hour you have,
I want to see you
in the medical lab.
I have an experiment
I need your help with.
Yes, ma'am.
SHADOW:
Your progress, Q?
As anticipated,
there are some problems.
I need time.
However, there is
the possibility
we won't have to terminate
the girl.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, my dear.
I've been told
I behaved badly.
I apologize.
Apparently, you had every reason
to chastise me,
but then again,
what's done is done, right?
I'd like to ask you
some questions.
Anything.
What exactly are the Q?
It would be so much easier
to show you than to tell you.
If you would agree
to take a short visit
to the Continuum...
No, just tell me.
Well, to put it simply,
we're omnipotent.
There's nothing,
nothing we can't do.
And what do you do
with this power?
Anything we want.
Do you use it to help others?
I think you've missed the point,
my dear.
Clearly, you've spent
far too much time with humans.
As a Q, you can have
your heart's desire instantly,
whatever that may be.
Would you like precious jewels,
works of art?
Would you like to walk
along the rings of Tautine?
I'm not interested
in any of those things.
Of course not.
You're a Q.
But surely
there must be something
that you want--
something that you
never dreamed was possible.
Tell me, Amanda,
what is it?
I'd like to know
what my parents
looked like...
my real parents.
How quaint.
So do it.
What do you mean?
Summon the image.
I don't know how.
Think about them.
Evoke the memory.
You can do it, Amanda.
Trust me.
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes!
In your mind,
return to the time
when you were an infant.
Think about
your parents.
Remember them.
Good.
Now, open your eyes.
They loved me.
Wait for it
to be metabolized.
Add another... 20?
Wait for it to be
metabolized over and over
and then wait
till the bacilli
can't be absorbed
anymore.
That's right.
Just be sure and record
the rate of mitosis
from each of the dishes.
Mitosis, right.
You seem distracted.
Well, I just saw my parents...
my real parents.
Q showed me how.
Can you imagine
how that felt?
No, I don't think I can.
You know, you were right.
I can't ignore
what's happened to me.
I just don't know
if I can cope with it.
Amanda, you are stronger
than you think.
You know...
when I saw them there,
right in front of me,
I realized
that I caused this to happen.
I wanted to see them
and I did.
If it were you--
if suddenly,
you could have
anything you wanted,
what would it be?
I have no idea.
No, think about it.
Really think.
If suddenly, you could make
anything happen,
what would it be?
Well, I would...
probably want to heal people--
people who are hopelessly ill.
Hmm.
Would you bring
your husband back?
Well, Amanda, I don't know.
And I don't think that I could
make a decision like that
until I was actually faced
with it.
I am faced with it.
Try to do the work.
I'll come back
and check on you later.
I thought she'd
never leave.
I don't know if I'll ever
get used to that.
It's time for
another lesson.
Well, I have to finish
this experiment first.
What are you doing?
We're delivering
live vaccine bacilli to Tagra.
I'm supposed to find
the best nutrient solution
so we can keep them living
while they're in stasis.
Fascinating.
Oh, I just had
a splendid idea.
Why don't we...
combine what you're
doing with our lesson
and we'll show you how
to finish in no time.
Well, I think that
I should finish it
the way Dr. Crusher
showed me first.
Oh, I'm sure
she'd be delighted
if we sped things along.
I mean, think
what it would mean.
You could double,
even triple the workload.
Well...
Good.
I guess so.
Now...
as you take a look
at the tissue samples,
form an image
in your mind.
Number One, Dr. Crusher has
some live vaccine bacilli
to be delivered to Tagra.
It'll have to be shipped
in a stasis field.
Will you make
the arrangements?
I'll get right on it.
Captain, message coming in
from Tagra IV.
On screen.
Enterprise,
I am Orn Lote, engineer.
We are having difficulties
with the reactor
that powers
the baristatic filters
on our southern continent.
We may have to shut it down
for repairs.
Perhaps my Chief Engineer
could be of assistance.
I hope so.
If we're forced
to disable the reactor,
it would take months to
reestablish the ionic currents
the filters have formed
in the atmosphere.
Send us
your design specifications.
I'm sure we'll be able
to help.
Thank you, Captain.
Captain?
What is it, Mr. Data?
I have some information
regarding Amanda Rogers'
parents.
Records indicate that they
died in Topeka, Kansas.
Their home was destroyed
during a tornado.
Tornado?
Why wasn't it dissipated
by the weather modification net?
Unknown, sir.
The bodies were discovered
in the rubble after
the storm had passed.
See if you can find out
any more details, Mr. Data.
I'd like to know
more about that storm.
Aye, sir.
Well, if it isn't
Number Two.
I was looking
for Dr. Crusher.
I didn't know what nutrients
she wanted
to send with the bacilli.
Uh, I'm not sure.
I'll tell her
to contact you.
Thanks.
You could stay here...
and wait for her, if you,
you know, wanted to.
Just tell her
I'll be in Shuttle Bay Two.
You're attracted to him.
I am not.
I think you are.
How repulsive.
( sighs )
How do you stand
that hair all over his face?
Doctor,
Commander Riker was
just here looking for you.
He said he'd be
in Shuttle Bay Two.
Thank you.
Have you finished
already?
Yes.
How did you
do it so quickly?
Well, Q helped me.
It took us
about half the time
that it would have
normally taken us.
That explains this data.
I needed to know
the rates of mitosis.
By artificially inflating them,
you made the experiment useless.
Now I have to do it
all over again.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
Don't be sorry.
If she wants to make things
difficult on herself,
that's her business.
Why did you interfere
with what she was doing?
She's a Q.
Making her plod
through human chores
is beneath her.
CRUSHER:
She asked not to be
treated differently.
That doesn't mean she
should be bored to death.
I don't interfere with
what you're teaching her...
You would be incapable
of interfering.
...and I don't think
it's asking too much
that you do the same.
( barking )
...and you stay out of mine.
When you
put it like that, I...
I think you're
absolutely right.
Captain.
Yes, Mr. Data.
I have further information
regarding the tornado
that killed Amanda
Rogers' parents.
What is it?
It was unusually compact,
yet extremely powerful.
Its recorded wind velocity
was characteristic
of a funnel
three times its size.
Download the files
to my ready room.
I'll study them there.
Aye, sir.
Have you been practicing
your teleportation?
Yes, but it's kind of hard.
I keep ending up somewhere
I don't want to be.
Well, it won't do
to be sloppy.
We should hone
your abilities.
I have a wonderful idea.
Why don't we play
a little game?
I'll hide somewhere
on the ship
and you find me.
But how do I know how...?
Q:
Don't worry, Amanda.
You can do it.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
If we can use
phase buffers,
we may be able
to devise a mechanism
that can be integrated
into the present system
while it is still
in operation.
You're still thinking
like a human.
Now do you understand?
What do humans
have to offer you
that even begins
to compare with that?
Your future
contains wonders
you can't even imagine.
The universe could
be your playground.
( door chimes )
Dr. Crusher
and Counselor Troi--
they're taking me to dinner.
You don't have
to eat, you know.
It's a nasty human habit
you could easily do without.
Hello, Amanda.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Well, Amanda, how
are you feeling
about all this now?
It must be overwhelming.
It was at first,
but actually,
now I'm enjoying myself.
Hello, ladies.
Hello, Will.
Commander Riker,
um, won't you join us?
I'd love to, but
I have other plans.
Hi.
So how are your
lessons going?
Is Q being patient with you?
Amanda?
What is this all about?
I thought it
might be nice
to spend some time
alone together.
I think it would be nice
if you took us
back to Ten-Forward.
Are you sure that
you wouldn't want
to stay here with
me for a while?
The moonlight
is so beautiful.
Isn't it nicer here
than at Ten-Forward?
Yes, it's very pleasant,
but that's not the point.
Oh.
I think it is.
No.
You can't snatch people
and put them into your fantasies
and expect them to respond.
Don't you like me?
Even just a little bit?
You're a very
lovely young lady,
but none of this is real.
( sighs ):
My feelings are real.
I know, but you can't
make someone love you.
Can't I?
Oh, Amanda...
you are so beautiful.
Do you love me?
More than anything.
You're right.
None of this is real.
I thought
it would be romantic,
but it's empty.
Amanda...
Just go back
to Ten-Forward.
Bonjour, mon Capitain.
You wanted to
speak with me?
I wanted to ask you about
Amanda's biological parents.
When they decided
to remain on Earth,
what was the reaction
in the Q Continuum?
We found it
incomprehensible.
Were they pressured to return?
Were they threatened
with any punishment
if they didn't?
What are you
driving at, Picard?
Well, the circumstance
of their death is quite odd.
A tornado somehow escaped
the weather modification net
and touched down
in only one spot--
Amanda's home.
Well, you can never
predict the weather.
Well, tornadoes develop
from existing storm fronts
but, you see,
there were no storm fronts
in Kansas that day.
Witnesses reported that
the funnel materialized
spontaneously,
directly over Amanda's home,
destroyed it, and disappeared.
If you say so.
I wasn't there.
Were Amanda's parents
executed by the Q Continuum?
And what if they were?
Well, I think she has
a right to know that
before she makes a choice
about her future.
Don't be foolish, Picard.
She has no choice.
She never did.
If she's truly Q,
then she must return
to the Continuum
where she belongs.
But if she were
some sort of a hybrid--
neither human
nor Q, then...
You would be so despicable?
Don't be naive.
You have no idea
what it means to be Q.
With unlimited power
comes responsibility.
Do you think
it is reasonable
for us to allow
omnipotent beings
to roam free
through the universe?
So what have you concluded?
Does she live
or does she die?
I haven't decided yet.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46193.8.
We have arrived at Tagra IV
and have begun delivering
supplies.
In the meantime,
I am faced with a crisis
of a different nature.
Look, I have no reason
to believe that Q is lying.
He claims he has orders
from the Continuum.
If Amanda cannot prove
that she is fully Q,
then he must kill her.
We have to tell her.
CRUSHER:
I don't know
if we should.
It almost seems cruel.
TROI:
Maybe she can
protect herself.
After all,
she has a great deal of power.
So did her parents,
it didn't save them.
I agree with the Counselor.
Amanda deserves to know
the truth of her situation.
We have no right
to hold such crucial information
from her,
but it isn't going to be easy
telling her.
What is your impression
of the field modulator,
Mr. Lote?
Quite ingenious.
Quite ingenious indeed.
I...
( coughs )
I'm amazed at the way
it can be incorporated
with the existing system.
Commander, we're
all loaded here.
We can head for the surface
whenever you're ready.
I'm eager to see
the field modulator
in place, Commander.
( coughs )
( inhaling deeply )
We'd better get going.
Yes.
Kill me?
But why?
They're not convinced
that you are fully Q
and... they are
also responsible
for your parents' death.
My parents?
But what right do they have?
Q? Answer me.
Are you afraid to face me?
She's such a plucky
little thing
now, isn't she?
I really do enjoy you,
you know.
Amanda's question
deserves an answer, Q.
You've made yourself
judge and jury
and if necessary,
executioner.
By what right have you
appointed yourself
to this position?
Superior morality.
Oh, yes.
I recall how you used
your superior morality
when we first encountered you.
You put us on trial
for the crimes of humanity.
The jury is still out on that,
Picard.
Make no mistake.
Your... arrogant pretense
at being the moral guardians
of the universe
strikes me
as being hollow, Q.
I see no evidence
that you are guided
by a superior moral code
or any code whatsoever.
You may be
nearly omnipotent--
and I don't deny
that your parlor tricks
are very impressive--
but morality.... I don't see it.
I don't acknowledge it, Q.
I would put human morality
against the Qs any day.
And perhaps...
that's the reason
that we fascinate you so,
because our puny behavior
shows you a glimmer
of the one thing
that evades your omnipotence:
A moral center.
And if so,
I can think
of no crueler irony
than that you should destroy
this young woman
whose only crime
is that she's too human.
Jean-Luc...
sometimes I think
the only reason I come here
is to listen to these wonderful
speeches of yours,
but this time,
your concern is unwarranted.
We've decided not to harm her
and we are prepared
to offer her a choice.
What kind of choice?
You can either come
to the Continuum with me...
Or...?
Now, this choice
is more difficult.
You have it within yourself
to refrain from using
the power of Q.
If you can do that,
you can stay here.
Then I'm staying here.
Think about this.
This is not so easy.
Your parents
were given this choice
and they were unable to resist
the temptation
of using their power.
All I've wanted
since this whole
thing began
is to become a normal
human being again.
I know I can resist.
Worf to Picard.
There is an emergency message
from Commander Riker.
I'm on my way.
RIKER:
Captain, the damage
to the reactor is greater
than the Tagrans
led us to believe.
The field modulator
is installed and operational,
but it's not going to be enough.
The reactor has already gone
into overload.
Can you correct
the problem?
Geordi is trying
to stabilize the unit now.
We will stay
as long as possible.
There are thousands
of people in this area.
If that reactor goes...
Commander, over here,
quickly!
Is this your doing, Q?
Not this time, Picard.
Mr. Worf,
see if there is any way
that we can cut through
the interference
and beam them out of there.
Aye, sir.
Captain, Geordi is trying
a neutrino infusion.
It may smother the reaction.
WORF:
Captain, there is too much
ionization in the atmosphere.
Transporters are useless.
LA FORGE:
It's no use.
The heat has fused
the injectors shut.
We're losing containment.
RIKER:
How long till meltdown?
LA FORGE:
A few minutes at most.
We're going to have to...
LOTE:
Commander, look at this.
This is impossible.
Captain, I don't know
what's happening,
but the reaction is stabilizing
on its own.
DATA:
Captain,
I am reading
a massive energy fluctuation
in the planet's atmosphere.
On screen.
DATA:
Atmospheric contaminants
have dropped to less
than one part per trillion.
The ecosystem has been restored
to its natural state.
Amanda?
I told you it would be
harder to resist
than you thought.
I couldn't let all
those people die.
Ever since
I got here,
I've been fighting this.
I've been denying the truth...
denying what I am.
I am Q.
Dr. Crusher...
I've decided that I can't stay.
I can't stay here.
Well...
now that you've come
to your senses,
let's go.
No. I want to go and
see my parents first.
It's going to take some
time to explain all of this,
so you'll have
to be patient.
I hope I can come back
and see you.
You're a Q.
You can do
anything you want.