Captain's Log,
Stardate 46235.7.
Ensign Ro, Keiko O'Brien,
Guinan, and I are
returning to the Enterprise
after a fascinating visit
to the planet
Marlonia.
And these pieces
I found
on the tertiary
level of the dig.
They're typical
of second-century
Marlonian cookware.
Look at
those markings.
They're very similar
to early
Taguan designs,
but the patterns are
more intricate.
They're much closer
to Buranian than Taguan.
You're on the most beautiful
planet in the quadrant,
and you spent your
entire shore leave in a cave?
It was a very
rewarding experience.
Look at these
fragments.
They're very nearly
in perfect condition,
and yet they're
700 years old.
So's my father.
Is that
a draebidium froctus?
Um... actually,
it's a draebidium calimus.
You can tell by
the shape of the leaves.
I didn't know you were
interested in plant biology.
I... took a class
at the academy.
I don't remember
very much, though.
WORF:
Enterprise to
Shuttlecraft Fermi.
This is the Fermi.
Go ahead, Enterprise.
We have just received
a distress signal
from the Starfleet
science team on Ligos VII.
Can you identify
the problem?
No, sir-- the call was
cut off in mid-transmission.
Lay in a course, and prepare
to engage at warp eight
as soon as we're on board.
Aye, sir.
We'll rendezvous with the
ship in three minutes, sir.
RO:
we're caught in some sort
of energy field.
Hard about.
Full impulse.
Aye, sir.
What's happening,
Mr. Worf?
The shuttle has been
enveloped by an energy field.
Its engines and life support
have failed.
Increase
to full impulse.
Bridge to
Transporter Room Three.
Prepare to beam
the shuttle crew back
once we're in range.
O'BRIEN:
Ready, sir.
I can't contact
the Enterprise.
There's too much
interference.
Transfer auxiliary power
to inertial dampers.
COMPUTER:
Warning, structural
failure imminent.
Have you got them,
O'Brien?
I'm trying, sir.
I can't get
a pattern lock.
The shuttle is
coming apart, Chief.
We've got to do it now.
I've got them.
There's a 40%
drop in mass.
I may have lost
one of them.
Thank you,
Mr. O'Brien.
Another moment
and...
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
According
to the bio-scans,
their DNA structure
is now consistent
with those of
preadolescents.
But as far as we can tell,
only their bodies were changed.
Their individual
intelligence
and their behavioral responses
are exactly the same
as they were
before the accident.
What happened
to the shuttlecraft, Number One?
The shuttle broke up
just after we beamed you out.
Mr. Data is coordinating
the salvage efforts
right now... sir.
What about the energy field
that the shuttle passed through?
We're trying to scan it,
but we're running into
a lot of interference--
it's going to take some time.
PICARD:
Well, we can't afford
to stay here any longer.
We'll leave
a class-4 probe behind
to study the energy field,
but the distress signal
from Ligos VII has
top priority.
Let me know
as soon as you have
any further
information, Doctor.
Number One,
you're with me.
Captain, I... need to run
some additional tests.
Of course,
the three of you
will remain as needed
to assist Dr. Crusher.
( sighs )
What?
You know, you make
a pretty cute kid.
Great, just what
I want to be-- cute.
Were you this much fun
when you were a kid?
I was in
a refugee camp.
"Fun" wasn't exactly
in my vocabulary.
What about now?
You're not in
that camp anymore.
Fun is being
back at work
in my own uniform.
Bridge.
Mr. Worf, prepare
to launch a class-4 probe
to study
the energy field.
I realize how unusual
this must seem.
My appearance is
the result of an accident
involving myself
and three other crew members,
the effects of which
Dr. Crusher is
currently working
to remedy.
I assure you,
I am captain Picard.
The probe, aye, sir.
Mr. Data, have you secured
all of the shuttle debris?
Almost. It is being stored
in Shuttle Bay Two...
sir.
Very well.
Ensign, as soon as
Mr. Data is finished,
take us to Ligos
at warp eight.
Captain, may I see you
privately for a few moments?
Of course.
Tea, earl grey, hot.
Have you been able to determine
the cause of our transformation?
Not yet. I'm still waiting
for some test results.
I see.
There are 103 members
of the science team
on Ligos VII.
We should prepare
Shuttle Bay Three
for a triage center
in case they have
large numbers of casualties.
We'll be ready.
I see that
Ligos VII is prone
to periodic volcanic
activity.
Perhaps the planet has
entered an active phase.
Jean-Luc?
We need to talk.
All right,
let's talk.
Are you here
to relieve me of duty?
I'd rather not have
to take that step.
I am still
Jean-Luc Picard.
My judgment,
my experiences,
my mental capacities
are all intact.
That's true...
for now.
But this could be
the first stage
of a condition
that may begin to affect
your mind,
as well.
But you see
no evidence of that.
Not yet.
What I do know is that
the captain of this ship
has undergone an extreme
physical transformation,
the ultimate
effects of which
I can't even
begin to guess.
You are asking me
to step down.
You are still
Jean-Luc Picard.
What do you think
you should do?
Commander Riker, please
take command of the ship
until further notice.
Understood.
So, what the hell
am I supposed to do now?
You're not supposed
to do anything.
That's what
"relieved of duty" means.
Well, I should be
doing something
instead of just
standing around,
waiting for them
to find a cure.
You're right.
Let's go play.
What?
I haven't been young
for a long time,
and I intend to enjoy
every minute of it.
Fine,
enjoy yourself.
What are you
going to do?
Go back to your
room and pout?
I am not
12 years old.
If I wanna go
to my quarters
and contemplate
my situation,
that does not mean
that I am "pouting."
Okay, okay.
I could use a...
cup of coffee.
How about you?
I'll get it.
Two coffees,
one with cream and sugar.
The other one...
Black, double sweet.
I know.
One double sweet.
Careful, that's hot.
Miles...
Sorry.
What's wrong?
It's...
I don't know,
but this feels wrong
somehow.
Miles Edward O'Brien,
I am still your wife!
Well, technically, yes.
Technically?
No, I mean,
of course you're my wife,
but you're also
ten years old.
Beverly said it's
actually closer to 12.
Now, that's not the point.
So, what is the point?
Is our marriage over?
I didn't say that,
but... well,
until they find a way
to reverse this...
this effect...
it's hard for me
to ignore the fact
that you're
a little girl.
What if they can't
find a way?
What if I'm like this
for the rest of my life?
What does that
mean for us?
For our family?
MOLLY:
Mommy?
What's wrong,
sweetheart?
I want Mommy
to read me a story.
All right.
What story would you
like to hear?
Not you.
I want Mommy!
What if Daddy reads you
a story tonight?
Will that be okay?
I'll be right back.
Keiko.
It's going to be
all right.
I promise.
We'll work this out.
How?
I don't know.
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
The Enterprise has reached
the Ligos system.
We have begun
to search for the missing
Federation
science team.
Dr. Crusher reports
no progress
on a cure for the members
of the shuttle crew.
( door chimes )
Come.
I came to see
how you're doing.
Well, I'll have
to speak to my tailor,
but otherwise
I'm well, thank you.
( sighs )
it's just so ridiculous.
I can't take myself
seriously like this.
Counselor...
if Dr. Crusher
can't find a cure--
if I have to stay
this way--
nobody's going to take me
seriously, are they?
I would say
the people
that know you
and have worked
with you
will be able to make
the adjustment eventually.
But there are some people
who would find it difficult
to accept
a 12-year-old captain.
In that case, I suppose
I'll just have to wait
until I grow up again
before I get another command,
which might be in
ten, maybe 15 years.
The question is,
what to do until then.
You're still
a Starfleet captain.
I'm sure there are
other assignments
you could be given
in the interim.
I've spent 30 years
of my life aboard starships.
I'm not about to sit
behind a desk now.
You could return
to the academy,
take another degree--
brush up on your Latin.
And be Wesley Crusher's
roommate.
I will admit that
returning to the Academy
does have
a certain appeal,
but I've spent my life
looking forward.
Going to the Academy again
feels like looking backward.
Then perhaps
you could spend the time
exploring
other interests.
Archaeology,
for instance.
Leave Starfleet?
Not permanently.
Just a sabbatical.
You could spend a few years
crawling through caves
and digging up artifacts
and still have
enough time to become
the youngest admiral
in Starfleet history.
It would give me a chance
to take up Dr. Langford's offer
and accompany her
to the ruins on Suvin IV.
But to leave
the Enterprise...
In a way,
you're very lucky.
You might have
a chance to do
what most people can
only dream about.
Have a second
childhood
without the pain
of growing up again.
This is captain Picard's
rybo-viroxic-nucleic structure
from a tissue sample
I took this morning.
It's the same as a sample
I took before the accident,
except it's missing several
of the key viroxic sequences.
It's been a long time since
I took genetics, Doctor.
RVN is one of
the key factors
in our development
during puberty.
Unlike DNA,
which never changes,
RVN takes on some
additional viroxic sequences
during adolescence.
Those sequences determine
how we develop
physically.
Without them, we wouldn't
mature into adults.
Exactly.
Now somehow,
those sequences
were eliminated
in the captain
and the others
during transport.
So, what do we do?
Well, we have
a couple of options.
These are the plants
Keiko was carrying
in the shuttle.
Whatever turned the crew
into children
turned these plants
into seedlings.
I accelerated
the growth on one of them,
and it developed into
a perfectly normal adult plant.
I don't suppose that
would work with people?
No, but at least we know
that if we do nothing at all,
they will probably grow up
just as they did before.
That's one option.
However, I do have
the adult RVN patterns
of all four of them.
I might be able
to send them back
through the transporter
pattern buffer
and replace
the missing sequences.
No, but we can't even
attempt to do that
until we know why this
happened in the first place.
If somehow they were to lose
more viroxic sequences...
They would get
even younger.
Chief, I got the sensor report
on the shuttle breakup.
Looks like the breakup began
near the starboard bulkhead.
There's some bulkhead
fragments over here.
Hmm.
Well, my visor's
picking up some...
torsional
stress damage,
some micro-fractures...
Hang on a second.
What's this?
Looks like tritanium
from the hull.
Yeah, but look.
That's not
tritanium anymore.
Somehow the molecular structure
of this alloy has been changed.
Broken down into its
constituent elements.
Ah, no wonder
the bulkhead shattered, huh?
Yeah, I want to get
a sample of this
down to engineering and run
a metallurgical analysis.
( sighs )
Well, this is exciting.
Would you rather be
playing with dolls?
I'd rather be doing
almost anything
other than sitting here
and watching you sulk.
This isn't
some kind of glorious
second childhood,
Guinan.
Our bodies have been
violated-- changed.
Doesn't that bother you?
Sure, it bothers me,
but at the moment
I can't do
anything about it,
so I might as well
enjoy it.
Enjoy what?
Where did you get the idea
that being short and awkward
is some kind of
wonderful gift?
There must have been
some part of childhood
that you didn't loathe.
Look, it was a long,
depressing period
of my life,
and I was grateful when
it was finally over.
I'd rather not
relive it.
I bet you were a jumper.
A jumper, you know.
Someone who jumps up and down
on furniture all the time.
What?
You were a jumper,
all right.
The quiet ones--
they always look
so innocent.
You think you can turn
your back on them.
Next thing you know, bam!
They're bouncing
on the bed.
That is the most
ridiculous thing
I've ever heard.
Most of the time,
I didn't even have a bed.
But you did have
one sometimes,
and I bet
you jumped on it.
I most certainly did not.
Yeah, I can see it
in your eyes.
You can barely
resist the urge
to leap up
and start jumping around
like a Tarkassian
razorbeast.
Guinan.
Oh, yeah--
oh, yeah.
This is ridiculous!
That's right,
and don't you dare
join me,
Ro Laren.
You don't like
jumping on beds.
Oh, yeah?
I can jump higher!
( laughing )
We think the shuttle was caught
in a molecular reversion field,
which caused the structure
of the ship to deteriorate.
When the field
penetrated the hull,
it also began to affect
the shuttle's crew.
When I tried
to beam them off,
I wasn't able
to get a lock
because the
reversion field
was masking part
of the patterns.
If the transporter
only registered
part of the RVN patterns,
that would explain why
the key sequences
are missing.
Exactly. With those
key sequences missing,
the transporter
reconstructed them
as children.
If they're right,
would you be able
to use the transporter
to reverse the effects?
I think so.
As long as there's
no reversion field
to mask their patterns,
we should be able to do it.
Chief,
can you adjust
the molecular imaging
scanners to accept...?
WORF:
Bridge to Commander Riker.
Go ahead.
We are entering orbit
around Ligos VII, sir.
On my way.
We'll discuss this later.
( sighs )
Standard orbit,
Ensign.
Any sign
of the science team?
We've been scanning the area
since we entered the system,
but our readings
are being disrupted.
Cause?
Extreme fluctuations
in the electromagnetic field.
However, there is no evidence
of stellar or seismic activity
which would cause
the interference.
Any response
to our hails, Mr. Worf?
No, sir. I've been
attempting to...
( console beeping )
Commander, two ships
de-cloaking, fore and aft.
Klingon Birds-of-Prey--
B'rel-class.
RIKER:
Maximum shields!
Take us out of
orbit, Ensign.
Mr. Worf, prepare
to return fire.
( alarm wailing )
Damage report.
We have lost
primary life support.
Switching to
secondary systems.
Lock phasers on target.
Bearing to port.
Phasers locked.
Fire.
Minor damage
to one ship.
Its shields are
holding.
Starboard power coupling
is down.
Warp engines are offline.
Shields?
Down to 13%.
Casualties reported
on Deck 26 and 27.
Sensors and secondary
generators are offline.
Life support
down to 67%.
Engineering,
status report.
Those last shots took out
auxiliary power
and emergency backup.
It's going to take
at least an hour
to get warp power
back online.
We have lost shields,
heavy casualties
on Decks 35 through 40.
I am detecting
transporter signatures
in three cargo bays.
We are being boarded, sir.
Come with me.
Initiate
intruder alert.
All security teams
report to...
Put down your weapons.
Computer, deactivate
all command functions.
Authorization:
Riker omega three.
All command
functions suspended.
This is Morta, we have
secured the bridge.
Begin transporting
all able-bodied adults
to the surface.
Come on!
Get up there.
They have locked out
the command functions.
You said they would
not have time.
You led the assault team.
You were too slow.
You dare to blame me?
We have secured
the ship, Daimon,
but Morta's incompetence has
denied us access to the...
My incompetence?!
Daimon, you know...
Enough.
Where is the captain
of this ship?
I'm in command
of this vessel.
Who are you, and on
whose authority do...?
I am Daimon Lurin,
and I declare
this ship to be a loss
and open to claim
according to the Ferengi
salvage code.
You will cooperate with
our salvage operations,
or we will begin...
executing your crew.
Is everyone
all right?
No fatalities or injuries
among the children.
The Ferengi have
taken control
of Main Engineering
and Decks 23 through 37.
Well, we have to also assume
that they've taken the bridge.
Captain, do you know
what they've done
with the younger children--
with my little girl?
Well, they're taking
all the adults
down to the surface.
Looks like they're keeping
all the children
on board the ship--
where was your daughter?
In primary care
on Deck 14.
She's probably still there
with the others.
I wouldn't worry.
We need to regain
control of the ship.
Options?
We could flood the ship
with anesthezine gas.
No, that's been
locked out with
the rest of the
command functions.
If they're
typical Ferengi,
they're probably
very pleased
with themselves
by now.
Maybe even getting
a little overconfident.
Agreed, they might
think they don't need
as much of their crew
to hold the ship.
We could use
the element of surprise
to give us
a tactical advantage.
Tactical advantage?
Jean-Luc,
look at your team
for a minute.
We're children.
We can't just stay here while
our ship is being commandeered.
I'm not suggesting
that we do,
but we can't act
as if we were still adults.
Well, what do you
suggest we do?
We look like
children.
Maybe it's time we started
acting like children.
Ahh...
i hope your profit margin's
pretty high for
this little adventure,
because you're risking war
with the Federation.
We're not affiliated
with the Ferengi alliance.
We are in business
for ourselves.
Yes, it will be
highly profitable.
For an investment of
two surplus Klingon ships,
a few repairs,
and some weapons,
we've netted a Federation
starship and her crew,
not to mention a planet
rich in vendarite.
So, that's what
this is all about.
What did you do with
the science team
that was on the surface?
They've proved
most, uh... helpful
in extracting the mineral.
You used them
as slave laborers.
The addition
of your crew
will greatly
speed up the process.
As for your ship...
I'm sure
that it will fetch
a handsome price
on the Romulan market.
But before
that can happen,
we need to regain access
to your central computer.
You don't really think
I'm going to help you.
I think that
the mines on Ligos VII
can be very hazardous.
Now... how many
people on your ship?
1,014.
Very hazardous,
Commander.
Hello, I'm the classroom
computer system.
What can I do for you
today?
Computer, display
interior security grid.
I'm sorry,
but I can't do that.
Would you like
to play a game?
No, I would not.
Computer, display an
internal schematic diagram.
I'm sorry,
but I can't do that.
Would you like to see
some interesting plants
or animals?
It's a child's
computer, remember?
Computer,
can you show me a picture
of the inside
of the Enterprise?
Yes, I can.
The Enterprise is
a galaxy-class starship.
Do you know how to spell
"Enterprise"?
"E-N-T-E-R...
Delete audio.
All right,
this'll have to do.
We're here.
There's
a service conduit
that runs to here
and then leads
to a Jefferies
tube here.
But you and Ensign Ro
will still have to cross
this corridor before you can
get to Main Engineering.
Captain!
PICARD:
Excellent.
Ready?
Make it so.
What the devil...?
I was just playing.
I'm sorry,
Captain.
Alexander,
would you mind
if I borrowed your toy
for a little while?
Go ahead.
Thank you.
After you.
( door opens )
( electronic whirring )
I've got the phasers,
Captain.
This is the first time
these Jefferies tubes
haven't seemed cramped.
How much farther
do we have to go?
Oh, about 50 meters.
Don't tell me
you're tired.
I'm not as young
as I used to be.
( both laughing )
This is it--
Main Engineering.
Now we wait.
Report?
Mission accomplished, sir.
The one in Sick Bay
never saw me.
Very good.
I'd say we're ready.
Have you figured out
how to get to the bridge?
I'm afraid I can only
think of one way.
What do you want?
I need to see
my father.
Go back inside.
I need to see him
right now.
Do not argue
with me.
Go back inside.
I need to see him now!
Now! Now! Now! Now!
Stop it!
You hurt me!
I want my father!
All right.
Just stop that.
PICARD:
Let me go!
Here he is.
Now be quiet.
What is going on?
Dad!
So, son,
how are you?
I'm okay.
And how are your friends--
Keiko and Guinan and Ro?
They're okay, too.
But...
What's wrong?
Well, we don't have
anything to do.
None of the games
are working.
I know, the Ferengi made Daddy
turn off the main computer.
Well, can't you just
turn on the kid's computer
in Schoolroom Eight?
We just want to play
a few games.
I don't know if
they'll let me, Jean-Luc,
but I will ask.
Thanks, Number One.
He's my number-one dad.
CHILD 1:
Here they come.
CHILD 2:
shh!
( door closes )
How did it go?
Did Commander Riker
get the message?
He understood.
We should have
access very soon.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I understand your son
was here to see you.
That's right.
We Ferengi do not
bring our offspring
along with us
aboard ship.
Then I suppose
that's your loss.
We consider our families
one of our strengths.
I think you will find that
they can also be a weakness.
Unless you release
the computer to our control,
I will execute
every child on this ship,
beginning with yours.
Even you wouldn't be
that cruel.
It is cruel to put
children in danger
by bringing them aboard
a starship in the first place.
Ahh!
All right...
just so you don't
harm my son.
You will release
the computer
and show Morta
exactly how to use it.
Ahh...
Computer, release
command control,
this station.
Authorization:
Riker omega three.
Command functions
restored.
Okay, Morta...
the Enterprise computer
system is controlled
by three primary main
processor cores,
cross-linked
with a redundant
melacortz ramistat
14-kiloquad
interface modules.
The core element...
is based on
an FTL nanoprocessor
with 25 bilateral
kelilactirals,
with 20 of those
being slaved
into the primary
heisenfram terminal.
Now, you do know what
a bilateral kelilactiral is?
Well, of course
I do, human.
I am not stupid.
No. Of course not.
This is the isopalavial
interface, which controls
the main firomactal
drive unit.
Don't touch that.
You'll blow up the entire
firomactal drive.
Oh, uh, wh-what...?
Wait... uh...
what is a--
a firomactal drive?
Well, just
explain it to me.
That is the firomactal
drive unit.
It controls
the ramistat core
and keeps the
Ontarian manifold
at 40,000 KRGs.
The firomactal drive
is powered by...
Command lockout
has been released.
Accessing
transporter.
Weapons deactivation
program is in place.
Transporter security
force field standing by.
We're ready.
Tag!
You're it!
( sighs )
Yes?
I found this in
the schoolroom.
Is it yours?
Hmm...
That's all of them except
for the two on the bridge.
Wait here until I return.
Yes, sir.
So, one more time,
the ramistat kiloquad
capacity is a function
of the square root
of the intermix ratio
times the sum of
the plasma injector
quotient...
Oh!
( door chimes )
Come in.
I believe you're
in my chair.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46236.3.
We have taken Lurin
and his men into custody.
The Ferengi Alliance has
quickly disavowed
any knowledge
of these renegades.
With the mining
operation closed,
and our crew back
on board,
we can now
turn our attention
to other problems.
Phase inducers
activated.
Energy levels nominal.
I'm loading
the adult patterns
into the buffer.
Transposition
matrix locked in.
That should do it,
Captain.
Energize.
How do you feel?
I feel fine.
Everything...
seems a little smaller.
It's my mother.
The funny thing is,
I never really drew a picture
of her when I was young.
It's just...
for some reason,
I wanted to now.
Well, that's the wonderful
thing about crayons.
They can take you to
more places than a starship.
It's my turn,
isn't it?
Only if you're ready.
It's not quite as bad
as I remembered it.
Being a child,
I mean.
Mmm.
Well...
we better get going.
what's the hurry?
I mean, the transporter
will still be there.
Why don't you pass me
the royal blue?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Okay, we can use
this one...
Did you do
this one, too?
Uh-huh.
I did all of them.
Oh.