Captain's Log,
Stardate 46271.5.
The Enterprise has entered
orbit of Deinonychus VII
but our scheduled rendezvous
with the supply ship Biko
has been delayed
for another 48 hours.
In the meantime,
many members of the crew
are taking advantage
of the delay
to pursue their own projects,
myself included.
( playing Mozart Trio
with clarinet and cello )
Computer, stop playback.
Change the clarinet
to an oboe.
Continue recording.
( door chimes )
Computer, pause playback.
Come.
Yes, gentlemen?
Captain, we'd like
your permission
to take the
engineering computer
off-line for a
couple of hours.
We're working on
a new interface
that would allow
Data to act as an
emergency backup
in the event
of a ship-wide
systems failure.
In theory,
my neural network
should be able
to sustain key systems
until primary control
is restored.
Hmm, it sounds like
an intriguing experiment.
I'll be interested
to see the results.
Permission granted.
It's possible we might
even be able to run
some secondary
systems through Data--
weapons control,
sensor...
Yes, I get the idea,
Mr. La Forge.
Thank you.
Please proceed.
Computer, begin playback
from the first measure.
( door chimes )
Computer, pause recording.
Come.
Jean-Luc, I need
to talk to you
about Something
For Breakfast.
Breakfast?
The play.
Ah, yes, well,
it's a very intriguing drama
but I really don't
have the time
it would take
to learn a part.
And, uh, anyway,
I'm not much of an actor.
That's no problem.
Oh?
Well, you wouldn't
be playing one
of the leads.
Oh.
It's a very small part--
only two lines.
Really?
It's the role
of the butler.
Well, I'll think about it
and let you know.
You would be
wonderful, Jean-Luc.
We're rehearsing
today at 1:30.
Computer, begin playback
from the first measure.
( door chimes )
Computer, pause recording.
Yes!
Captain, I
am sorry to
interrupt...
No. Please, Mr. Worf,
come in.
I was hoping
to take advantage
of the Biko's delay
by staging ship-wide
security drills.
I have planned a
tentative schedule.
Oh, yes, this is
very impressive, Mr. Worf.
But we'll be taking on
new personnel
at Starbase 118
in a few weeks.
Surely, the drills
can wait until then.
In that case, I will use
the time to perform
maintenance checks on
the forward phaser array.
Mr. Worf, is there
some reason
why you are trying to
give yourself more work?
No, sir. I simply wish
to use the extra time...
Enjoy yourself.
You have
the free time.
Use it.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Computer, continue recording
and playback once more...
from the top.
( electronic zaps and whirs )
( door opening )
Father!
What did he say?
The captain saw fit to
release me from my duties.
You mean you can go?
I can go.
Saddle up, Father.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( birds cawing )
( dog barking distantly )
( creaking )
( jangling footsteps
approaching )
( barking continues )
Where are we?
Deadwood.
19th-century Earth.
The ancient West.
What is our function here?
You are the sheriff,
and I'm the deputy.
So...
we are in
law enforcement.
Right.
Geordi?
Mm-hmm?
I have noticed that
you have not shaved.
Are you attempting
to grow another beard?
Matter of fact,
I am, Data.
What do you think?
As is the case with many
natural growth processes
it is difficult
to envision the
end product
based on an
intermediate stage.
You're right.
Give it
a few more days.
Okay, I'm going to
need to access
your auxiliary inputs.
One moment.
I must admit, Data.
I never get used
to seeing you like this.
I do not understand.
You are constantly working
on similar electronic systems
yet their appearances
do not disturb you.
Yeah, but you're not just
another electronic system.
Thank you, Geordi.
Nor are you just another
biological organism.
All right,
that should do it.
You ready?
Yes.
Establishing
computer linkup.
Interface complete.
All right,
let's see what you can do.
( whistle )
You wrote this
holodeck program yourself?
Well, Mr. Barclay
helped a little.
I must have a little talk
with Mr. Barclay.
( gunshot )
( dog barking )
( playing jaunty melody )
( indistinct conversation )
If ever I find the varmint
that drew this
he'll be sorry
he ever put pen to paper.
I'm ten times uglier
than that, ain't I?
( laughing loudly )
Shut up.
You laugh so much,
it's a wonder
you ain't got
flies in your mouth.
( laughing )
You're a very funny man,
Se単or Eli.
That's the bad guy.
His name's
Eli Hollander.
They call him
"The Butcher of Bozeman."
He's killed 23 men.
He's the meanest and
the toughest gunslinger
in the West.
You have to watch
him-- he's fast.
So I am here
to apprehend him?
If you can.
( piano music continues )
You are under arrest.
Is that so?
WOMAN:
Sakes alive!
Did you see that?
You will come with me.
No, no, no.
Computer, freeze program.
What is wrong?
That was too easy.
It has to be
harder to beat
the bad guys.
Otherwise,
it's no fun.
Computer, increase program
difficulty to level four.
Go back to where my
father and I first walked
into the saloon.
Come on, Father.
( plays piano flourish )
( same melody plays )
If ever I find the varmint
that drew this
he'll be sorry
he ever put pen to paper.
I'm ten times uglier
than that, ain't I?
( laughing loudly )
Shut up.
You laugh so much,
it's a wonder
you ain't got
flies in your mouth.
( laughing )
You're a very funny man,
Se単or Eli.
Where are they going?
They don't want to get
hit by the bullets.
You... are under arrest.
Well...
Looks like Sheriff Worf's
here to arrest me.
That don't sound like
a bright idea...
...do it?
( cocking rifle )
You have been accused
of committing a homicide.
If you mean murder
then I guess
I'm guilty.
I've killed 23 men,
Sheriff.
One more ain't going to make
much of a difference.
Of course, shooting
someone as ugly as you
couldn't be considered
a crime, could it?
Was you born that way
or did your mama marry
an armadillo?
( laughing loudly )
Sheriff, look out!
I'm beginning to see
the appeal of this program.
Don't twitch
a whisker, Sheriff,
'less you want
a shave.
Okay, boys.
Saddle up!
But first...
get their
money and jewelry.
You are a
murderer and a thief.
A man's got to
make a living.
( gunshot )
( drawls ):
I suggest you find
a new line of work.
I asked Counselor Troi
to join us.
She loves
Western stories.
You'll regret this,
stranger.
I am now attempting to access
the long-range sensor array.
Forward sensor array
coming on line.
We're getting
a clear scan.
I will perform
a routine maintenance check
on the starboard inertial
damping system.
Dampers on line.
Maintenance check
in progress.
Data, I think we're
onto something here.
Let's see what
you can do
with the secondary systems.
Try gravitational
control.
Initiating gravit...
What's wrong?
There appears to be
an energy fluctuation
in my neural net.
I am disconnecting my
interface to the computer.
Interface deactivated.
You all right?
I have experienced
a brief power surge
in my positronic subprocessor,
but I am fine.
Maybe the
interface coding
isn't as stable
as we thought.
Looks like we've got
a couple of hours
of systems analysis
before we can
try this again.
Let's check
the interface programming.
What are his rights
in this century?
Is there a trial,
or shall I execute him?
We're supposed to
hold him till the
U.S. marshal comes.
And then we'll
take him to Rapid
City for a trial.
Frankly, I don't think
I'll be around here
that long.
Not after my old man
hears about this.
What "old man" are you
referring to?
My pa.
When he breaks me out
of this tin can
gravedigger will
be working overtime.
Your pa is no match
for Sheriff Worf.
Yes, when your "pa" comes,
we will be ready for him.
( chuckles ):
Yeah.
TROI:
He's right.
You're no match
for the Hollanders.
I'm sure that the three of us
can handle any problems.
Hold on.
I was just passing through
town, saw a little trouble
and thought I'd lend a hand.
But I ain't one of
your deputies, Sheriff.
Counselor, I would appreciate
some support in this matter.
Durango!
I'm called Durango.
Yes, uh, Counselor Durango.
Perhaps
you would consider
becoming a temporary deputy.
For a price.
$500.
Alexander, we require
large amounts of currency.
Yes, sir.
I'll go to the bank
and make a withdrawal.
Deanna, how do you know
so much about this period
in Earth's history?
My father used to
read me stories
from the ancient West
when I was a little girl.
I must admit,
I always wanted
to play the part
of the "mysterious stranger."
Oh!
You are so brave.
Facing down
that evil man
like you did.
Why, thank you,
Miss...?
Annie, you big galoot!
You best not forget
that tonight
'cause I'm going to
make you a beefsteak
and some gooseberry
cobbler for dessert.
Sounds delicious.
And I bought
some special candles
for the table setting--
pure beeswax.
I will not be able
to come this evening.
I have a prisoner.
I'll keep an eye on him
for you, Sheriff.
You two go have
a good time.
That's very
considerate of you
but I would be negligent
in my duties if I did not stay.
I am sorry, Ms. Annie.
It's another woman,
ain't it?
It's that
floozy down there
at Miss Langford's
House of Pleasure!
Who?
You sure got a way
with women, Sheriff.
( coughs )
Computer, activate
Picard Mozart Trio, Program 1.
Play back tracks one,
two and three.
Tempo allegro.
( music begins )
( sound glitches )
( tape fast-forwarding )
( "The Slavonic Dances"
plays loudly )
Computer, stop playback.
Computer, identify
musical composition.
Picard Mozart Trio,
Program 1.
Okay.
Let's work through act two
from the beginning.
Whenever you're ready.
( clearing throat )
"Felis catus is your
taxonomic nomenclature.
"An endothermic quadruped
carnivorous
by nature..."
Hold it.
Will, what are
you reading?
The lines. Why?
That's not
the right dialogue.
"Your visual, olfactory,
and auditory senses
contribute to your..."
I recognize it.
This is Data's poetry.
What?
The play's gone.
I just keep getting
more poetry.
Well, the PADDs
are functioning normally.
It seems to be a problem
with the information
retrieval net.
Somehow, when you tried
to call up your play
the computer accessed
Data's literary files.
Geordi, perhaps
this problem
is related to
our interface experiment.
Hmm. We'd better run
a level-2 diagnostic
on the computer
to see if this problem
has spread
to any other systems.
And I will perform
a self-diagnostic.
That's a good idea.
You will let me know
if you find the play?
Oh, yeah, don't worry.
It's in here
somewhere.
( muffled moaning )
( muffled gasp )
We got him, Jefe.
Where's my boy?
I'm not supposed
to be kidnapped now.
Computer, freeze program.
Hey!
Computer,
freeze program.
You want us to kill him,
Se単or Frank?
No.
He's more
valuable to us...
alive.
Feline supplement 127.
Spot, I have formulated
a new mixture of foods
specifically designed for
your highly selective tastes.
( meowing )
I find it extremely difficult
to predict what you
will find acceptable.
Perhaps hunger will compel you
to try it again.
( meowing )
Spot, you are disrupting
my ability to work.
( meowing )
( thick Texas drawl ):
Vamoose, ya little varmint!
( plays tinkling melody )
What'll it be?
I was looking
for my deputy.
Perhaps you have
seen him.
Nope.
What'll you have?
Um...
Klingon fire wine.
( laughing )
This ain't Kansas City.
We ain't got none of that
fancy European stuff here.
Maybe I should
get you a sherry.
Ain't that what
they serve at
Miss Langford's?
It is, ain't it?
Ain't it?
Humph.
( footsteps approaching )
( dog barking )
( music stops )
Howdy, Sheriff.
Commander.
What are you doing here?
The name is
Frank Hollander.
What are you
looking at?
Nothing.
Nothing at all,
Mr. Hollander.
What do you want?
My boy.
That is impossible.
Your son is to stand trial
for murder.
Well, then
we'll just have
to work something out.
Is there anything
you... want
in exchange
for my boy?
You have nothing I want.
Is that so?
What about your...
deputy?
What about him?
Where is he?
I do not negotiate
with criminals.
Your son will stand trial.
Not so fast.
( yelps )
Commander, what
are you doing?
I ain't in the mood
for games, Sheriff.
Commander?
Computer, freeze program.
I wouldn't walk out that door
if I was you, Sheriff.
( door opening )
What's wrong?
The holodeck safeguards
are not functioning.
Alexander's in trouble.
My God!
You've been shot.
Computer, end program.
Troi to Captain Picard.
Troi to security.
There's another
character in
the program--
Hollander's father.
And he looks like
Commander Data.
Data?!
But it is not
Data.
I-I cannot explain.
I believe he has
taken Alexander.
ELI:
Aw, now, isn't
that a shame?
Poor Sheriff's
been injured.
What's the matter?
Was my pa
a little too rough on ya?
( laughing )
Data?
What?
Why is the computer
creating characters
that look like Data?
Where have they
taken my son?
Where is he?
Temper, temper, Sheriff.
My pa ain't going to
like it if I come
home all bruised.
Worf, wait!
We have to remember--
even though
the holodeck
safeguards
may be off
this is still
a program.
If we can just
get to the end
of this story
the way it
was designed
to play out
the program will
automatically
terminate.
You are right.
I will begin by speaking
to the people of this town.
Perhaps somebody witnessed
Alexander's abduction.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Commander La Forge and Mr. Data
believe they have found
the cause
of the mysterious malfunctions
which have been plaguing
the ship.
We think our interface
experiment may have caused
one of the computer's
core subroutines
to be altered.
When the interface
malfunction occurred
subroutine C-47
was replaced
by elements
from my personal programming.
What does C-47 control?
Library computer access,
replicator selection
recreational programming.
No critical systems.
That would explain why
your music composition program
began playing
"The Slavonic Dances."
I have been analyzing
the collected works
of Anton Dvorak.
It's the same with
Dr. Crusher's play
and with the food
replicators.
The replicators
on decks four through nine
are producing nothing
but cat food.
Cat food?
I have been formulating
nutritional supplements
for Spot.
Oh... when can you
correct the problem?
We are currently attempting
to isolate
the corrupted
circuit pathways.
I reckon the process
should take
less than two hours.
What did you say?
I said the process should
take less than two hours.
No. You said,
"I reckon."
According to my memory logs,
I did not use those words.
( drawls ):
Y'all must be mistaken.
There, Data,
you did it again.
( drawls ):
Did what?
Uh... Mr. La Forge
perhaps you should take
Mr. Data to engineering.
See if you can
find the problem.
Aye, sir.
( sighing )
( cards shuffling )
( tapping )
Can I help you
with something?
( knocking )
I spoke
to several witnesses
who saw Alexander
being abducted
as he was leaving the bank
by one of Hollander's men.
We must begin a systematic
search of the town.
Worf, we've got
another problem.
I saw Eli playing cards.
He was shuffling
the way Data does
when he plays poker.
He doesn't just
look like Data.
He has Data's abilities
which means his father
probably does also.
( knocking )
I come to see my boy.
Remove your weapon.
Better take a good look
at that gun, Sheriff.
You might be
seeing it again real soon.
Pa!
Eli!
How they
treating you, boy?
Real bad, Pa.
Ain't fed me
since I got here
and that sheriff's been
roughing up on me
something fierce.
Don't you worry, boy.
Sheriff's
going to pay.
( whispers ):
Who's the stranger?
I don't know.
She ain't
said her name
but she's in cahoots
with the sheriff
and she's mighty mean
with that Winchester.
You sit tight, boy.
I'll have you home
in time for supper.
I'm going to give you
one more opportunity, Sheriff,
to avoid a ugly situation.
Release my boy.
I have reconsidered
your offer.
I will release your son
in exchange for my deputy.
I thought you might have
a change of heart.
Meet me in two hours.
You be in front of
the saloon.
I'll be in front
of the livery stable.
Strangers ain't invited.
Agreed.
In every Western
I've ever read,
the villains always
break their word.
He can't be trusted.
But we have made
an honorable agreement.
They're not concerned
with honor, Worf.
This is
the ancient West.
There's a gunfighter
out there
who has the speed and
accuracy of an android...
... and in two hours, he's
going to try to kill you.
Mr. Data.
Howdy, Commander.
Geordi, what
have you found?
( drawl ):
Well, we figure part
of my memory structure
( in normal voice ):
was replaced with information
from the computer's
recreational database.
Specifically,
the files relating
to the American
19th-century West.
That would explain
the accent.
You got it, pardner.
This is a result of the
experimental interface?
I'm afraid so,
but we've initiated
a progressive memory purge
to restore Data's programming
to its original state.
He should be back to normal
in a couple of hours.
And what about the computer's
recreational database?
We've started a memory purge
there, as well.
That should take
another hour, maybe two.
Commander...
you just sit tight.
We'll have this all fixed up
in time for supper.
Good.
WORF:
I will be positioned here
at the eastern end
of the street.
Frank Hollander says
he will approach
from this end.
Now, when he reaches this point,
he will be within range.
Understood.
What about Alexander?
Well, there's a rain barrel
in front of the saloon.
It should be enough
to stop the bullets.
( knocking )
You would not believe
what I went through
to get Old Man Newsome
to give up
his telegraph machine.
Ah...
Excellent.
Lord knows why I keep risking
my life for you, Sheriff.
( clearing throat )
Oh, yes, uh,
thank you, Ms. Annie.
I'm in your debt.
( clock chimes )
I have connected
the communicator's energy cell
to serve as the
power source.
How long
will the field last?
No more than
15 seconds.
It is highly unstable.
Let's hope it's enough.
( bird cawing )
( dog barking )
( spurs jangling )
Eli, get down!
Alexander!
Don't even think
about it.
Se単or Frank!
Go ahead, shoot me.
Do not show your face
in this town again.
Let's go.
( birds cawing )
Father!
Are you all right?
Yes.
End program.
I don't understand this.
The story
should be over.
What's left?
Computer, end program.
Sheriff!
You're as handy
with a shootin' iron...
... as you are with a woman's
heart.
Computer, end program.
Computer!
Now!
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46278.3.
Both Commander Data
and the ship's computer
have been restored
to normal operation.
Our rendezvous
with the supply ship Biko
has proceeded as planned.
Father...
after what happened
I guess
you'll never want
to go back to
the ancient West.
The town of Deadwood may
face danger once again.
If they do, they will
need a sheriff...
and a deputy.