Commander, is it
your intention
to continue
to grow your beard?
Actually, I...
I'm not sure yet.
Why, Worf?
I was just asking.
Seven card stud,
one-eyed jacks are wild.
Frankly, Geordi,
I like the beard.
Thank you, Commander.
You know, I have always been
a little suspicious
of men in beards.
And why is that?
I don't know, it's as if
they're trying to
hide something.
Hide?
Don't be ridiculous, Doctor.
The beard is an ancient
and proud tradition.
Mmm.
Some of the most
distinguished men in history
have worn beards, Doctor.
I know, but after the
razor was invented,
I think beards became
mostly a fashion statement.
I'm not concerned with fashion.
To a Klingon, a beard
is a symbol of courage.
Mmm.
I think it's a sign of strength.
Sure, and, of course,
women can't grow beards.
Doctor, it sounds to me
like you feel that beards
are nothing more
than an affectation.
I do.
But there's nothing
wrong with that.
I mean, women wear makeup
and nail polish.
I just think it's time
that you men admit it.
My beard is not
an affectation.
Oh. Well, then you wouldn't
mind shaving it off.
I could lose it in a minute.
I've just gotten used to it.
Okay, then why don't we
up the stakes a little,
and if I win, all of you
shave your beards off.
Wait a minute.
What if you lose?
What are you gonna give up?
I'm open for suggestions.
Well, I've always wanted to
see you as a brunette.
Oh, I did that
once when I was 13.
I couldn't change it
back fast enough.
Makes me even more curious.
( laughing )
Fine. If one of you wins,
I'll become a brunette.
Are we on?
LA FORGE:
Yeah.
Yeah, we'll take that bet.
Hm.
Looks like you have the
hand to beat, Commander.
LA FORGE:
200.
I'm in 200.
Geordi...
Ah.
PICARD:
This is the captain.
We have arrived at
the Tyran system.
All senior staff to the Bridge.
Wait.
I'm sorry. You heard
the captain-- duty calls.
I guess we'll have to do this
some other time.
( chuckling )
( sighing )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46307.2.
We have just come into orbit
of Tyrus VII-A
to monitor progress on
the Tyran particle fountain,
a radically new
mining technology.
So far, the project has been
fraught with problems
and is well behind schedule.
Mr. La Forge
has been assigned
to evaluate the situation.
Dr. Farallon,
the original plans
called for the particle
fountain to lift
500 kilograms per minute
from the planet's surface.
Now, so far, we haven't
even come close to that.
Well, that's why I want to
increase the stream density.
That should boost the
lift capacity by 72%.
Yeah, but you realize,
of course, you're gonna be
overloading the field
generators in the process.
Not if we distribute
the overload evenly
throughout the system.
Doctor, forgive me, but maybe
we should concentrate
on completing this
phase of the project
before we start talking
about redesigning it.
Commander, I know you're here
to evaluate this project.
Starfleet is considering
using a particle fountain
on Carema III.
They wanna know
how feasible it is.
And will your opinion
be the deciding factor?
No, not really.
I'll make my report
to Captain Picard.
He'll make the official
recommendation to Starfleet.
They'll decide.
Well, what's your
feelings so far?
Well, it seems to me
the question
we need to
be asking is,
is this technology
more efficient
than conventional
mining techniques?
Commander, I know
we've had problems here.
It seems like nothing's
gone right.
It's taking a lot
longer than I thought
to get the particle stream
to full strength,
but I know it can work.
This is the direction
that mining
is going to take in the future,
and it should be
implemented on Carema III.
I know this can be
potentially very exciting.
All right...
I wanna show you something
I've been working on--
something that might help us
complete this project
more quickly.
I've used these on a
limited basis, but--
( rumbling )
( people shouting )
( alarm beeping )
DATA: Enterprise to
Commander La Forge.
I am reading significant
power fluctuations
from the station core.
Please report.
La Forge here.
We have a malfunction
in one of the power grids.
We're losing particle stream
confinement.
DATA:
Do you require assistance?
Stand by.
I'm sorry, Doctor,
I think
we're gonna have
to shut it down.
It took four months to get
the particle flux
up to this level.
If we shut it down,
it'll take another four months
just to get it back.
Look, we've got less
than five minutes
before we lose containment.
When that happens,
the particle stream is gonna
flood this entire station.
We're gonna have to
shut it down then anyway.
Then we'll just have
to fix the power grid.
Yeah, but how
do we do that?
The defective grid is
200 meters down conduit A-2.
We have to disassemble four
bulkheads just to get to it.
Well, here's the
perfect opportunity
to show you what
I had in mind.
What is this?
This is an exocomp--
the experiment I was
telling you about.
( electronic whirring )
If it doesn't work,
we'll still have time
to shut down
the fountain.
DATA:
Enterprise to La Forge.
What is your situation?
Unchanged for the moment,
but we're working on it.
Listen, if this thing
doesn't work soon,
we're gonna have to shut
this thing down, all right?
( power coming on line )
( sighs )
The confinement field
is at full strength.
Particle flux steady.
All power levels
are back to normal.
Commander La Forge,
please report.
We're-- we're fine, Data.
The power grid is
fully restored.
Malfunction seems
to have been repaired,
and operations over
here at the station
are all back to normal.
How were you able to accomplish
the repair so quickly?
You know...
I'm not exactly sure.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46315.2.
Repairs to the particle
fountain seem to have succeeded
and it is now functioning
smoothly.
Dr. Farallon is coming aboard
to demonstrate the device
that carried out the repairs.
Energize.
Aye, sir.
DATA: Welcome to the
Enterprise, Doctor.
I am Lieutenant
Commander Data.
Mr. Data, I was hoping I'd
have a chance to meet you.
I've done extensive studies
of your positronic network.
And I have studied your design
for the particle fountain.
I find the concept to
be highly innovative.
Thank you.
I am curious
how you were able
to repair the power
grid so quickly.
This should make it
clear, Commander.
Why don't we set it up
in Engineering?
Is it true that your
computational speed
is limited only by
the physical separation
of your positronic links?
DATA: Actually, that is
no longer the case.
I have recently converted
my interlink sequencer
to asynchronous operation,
which removed the
performance constraint.
Doctor... this way, please.
I see, but how
did you resolve
the signal fragmentation?
The interlink sequencer
is now bi-directional.
It compensates for the
asynchronous mode distortion
arising from the
resonant field.
Yes.
That's fascinating.
Does the sequencer require
any buffering system
to eliminate interference
from the positronic matrix?
FARALLON: We've been
using devices like this
on Tyrus VII for years.
The basic unit is a common
industrial servomechanism.
A few years ago, I started
tinkering with one.
This is the result.
Boridium power converter.
Axionic chip network.
That's very impressive.
You know, in terms of
sheer computational speed,
this little guy might be able
to compete with you, Data.
Oh, the exocomps
don't come close
to Data's sophistication.
Exocomps?
That's what
I call them.
Let's say you had an
anti-matter flow converter
that was fluctuating.
How would you repair it?
The correct procedure would
be to adjust the converter.
With what?
A mode stabilizer.
Okay, let me input the
problem into the exocomp.
A fluctuating anti-matter
flow converter.
Now, let's see what happens.
LA FORGE:
A mode stabilizer.
Very nice.
You have incorporated a
micro-replication system
into the device in order
to fashion tools.
It's more than that.
I designed the exocomps
to be problem solvers.
Whenever they
perform a task
they've never done before,
the micro-replicator
creates new circuit pathways
within the unit's memory.
So, in a sense,
they are learning.
FARALLON:
Exactly.
The more situations
they encounter,
the more circuit
pathways they build.
They become better
tools as they work.
It's very impressive technology,
that's for sure.
Once it's out of
the experimental stage,
there'll be plenty
of applications.
Commander, I'm hoping the
experimental stage is over.
When are we supposed
to brief Captain Picard
on the status of the
particle fountain?
1600 hours.
Good.
I'll have a proposal to make.
Captain, I know you're
supposed to give
your evaluation
to Starfleet today.
I'd like you to postpone that
report another 48 hours.
The Enterprise is scheduled to
leave the Tyran system tomorrow.
If I'm to change that plan,
I'll need a very good reason.
I realize that, sir.
If you're going to make
a recommendation to Starfleet
about using the particle
fountain on Carema,
it seems only fair
that you should see it
operating at full strength.
Agreed.
I think I can
complete the project
and boost the efficiency
of the particle stream
if I use exocomps-- the new
devices I've constructed.
I understand
one of these devices
successfully repaired
a faulty power grid.
Yes, sir.
I've been testing them
on a limited basis, but I
think they're ready
to be used on
a larger scale.
Mr. La Forge,
what are your thoughts?
Well, I guess the only risk
is in falling
even further behind.
I'm willing to
take that risk.
Mr. Data?
Exocomps are highly
sophisticated devices, sir.
If they perform
up to expectation,
their potential to advance
this project is considerable.
PICARD:
I'm inclined to agree.
I don't think that 48 hours
is too much time to risk,
particularly when the
gains are so substantial.
You may proceed, Doctor.
Thank you, sir.
If possible,
I'd like Commander Data
to work with me.
Thank you, Doctor.
I welcome the opportunity.
Commander,
there's a plasma conduit
in one of the access tunnels
that's ready to be sealed.
It's the perfect
job for an exocomp.
I agree, Doctor.
Well, Mr. Data, what is
your analysis so far?
I have successfully
completed 14 separate tasks
with this exocomp
in the past hour.
I estimate it would take
two people nine hours
to complete the same tasks.
I would characterize the unit's
performance as excellent.
I hope Commander La Forge
and Captain Picard
agree with you.
I am confident they will.
Commander La Forge
is especially--
Hmm... it didn't finish
sealing the plasma conduit.
Let me send it back in.
It is not accepting
your commands.
Maybe there's
a malfunction
in the control processor.
Let me see if I
can override it.
Doctor?
I'm all right.
The control PADD
just overloaded.
( whirring and beeping )
What's the matter
with this thing?
DATA: Second Officer's Log,
Stardate 46315.5.
The unexplained behavior
of the exocomp
has greatly puzzled both
Dr. Farallon and myself.
We have brought
the defective unit
to the Enterprise
for investigation.
FARALLON: The exocomp came
out of the plasma conduit.
We tried to override
the commands
and send it back in,
but it just shut down.
It's been completely
unresponsive ever since.
Well, let's see what
our computer has to say.
Geordi, the interface circuitry
which links the exocomp
to the control PADD
is completely burned out.
That's strange.
Is there any indication
of secondary power surges?
No.
But what's going on there?
Data, increase
the magnification
of section Gamma-Four.
Interesting.
The number of new
circuit pathways
has increased by 632%.
Oh, no.
What is it?
Sometimes an exocomp starts
forming large numbers
of new pathways
totally at random.
Eventually, it reaches a
point where it shuts down,
just like this one.
Doctor, the new pathways
do not appear
to be interfering
with the original circuitry.
Once the exocomp is this
badly corrupted, it's useless.
You have to erase the unit
and start all over again,
and there's no time
for that now.
That leaves you with only two.
It's gonna
slow you down.
Yes, Commander,
you have the right
to point out that
you told me so.
I only wanted to
say that we'd be happy
to add on an extra shift
to pick up the slack.
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm touchy
these days.
It's okay, you've got
a lot on your shoulders.
Well, I'd better
get back to it.
Thanks, Commander.
Data.
I feel sorry for her.
This project has had
nothing but problems.
Why did that plasma
conduit explode?
Apparently, there was
a micro-fracture
in the conduit wall.
The fault did not register
on our instruments.
Hmm, I guess it's
a good thing
the exocomp
malfunctioned.
Almost seems like it knew
just when to leave.
Geordi, are you
implying the exocomp
exhibited some form of
self-preservation?
Of course not.
PIERSON: Lieutenant Pierson
to Commander La Forge.
Sir, could you join us
in the systems monitor room?
On my way.
Computer, perform
a Level-1 diagnostic
of the exocomp's
command module.
COMPUTER: The command pathways
are functioning normally.
How can that be if the interface
circuitry is burned out?
COMPUTER: The interface
circuitry has been repaired.
Curious.
Computer, access
the exocomp's sensor logs.
Confirm that there was a failure
in the interface circuitry
within the last 12 hours.
COMPUTER: Confirmed.
Interface failure occurred
at 1150 hours today
when the exocomp produced
a power surge
which burned out the linkage.
How and when
was it repaired?
COMPUTER:
The exocomp activated
a self-repair program
at 1340 hours.
Why would the exocomp burn out
its own interface circuitry
and repair it two hours later?
COMPUTER:
Unknown.
Here you are.
I thought you'd be
hard at work by now.
I wanted a quiet cup of
tea before I went back.
Gathering strength,
I guess.
Well, I've come to tell
you that I've assigned
two engineering teams to work
on the particle fountain.
Thank you, Commander.
I'm grateful.
You know, I really
want you to know
that I do admire the
work that you've done,
and I'm sorry that the
exocomps aren't working out.
You were right.
I'm trying to
move too fast.
I guess I lack that
conservative streak
most scientists have.
I always seem to be out there
on the edge, taking chances.
You know, I'll bet you were
the kind of little girl
who was always climbing
one branch higher
than the other kids.
Anything to get to
the top of the tree.
And I bet you never fell.
Oh, no, I fell
all the time.
Usually breaking a bone
in the process.
I just never let it stop me.
Well, if it comes down to
sheer determination,
I know you'll get
this particle fountain built.
You're right about that,
Commander.
I've spent the last six years
of my life on this project.
It's the first thought
I have when I wake up
and the last
before I go to bed.
Whatever it takes to prove
this technology, I'll do.
Doctor, if you wish
to master the bat'leth sword,
you must learn to strike and
avoid in the same motion.
I almost got in
under your guard, Worf.
Almost.
Well, I'll keep that
in mind next lesson.
Doctor...
Are you injured?
Only my pride, Data.
Thanks.
Doctor, what is the
definition of life?
That is a big question.
Why do you ask?
I am searching
for a definition
that will allow me to
test an hypothesis.
Well, the broadest
scientific definition
might be that life
is what enables
plants and animals
to consume food,
derive energy
from it, grow,
adapt themselves to
their surroundings,
and reproduce.
Hmm.
And you suggest that
anything that exhibits
these characteristics
is considered alive?
In general, yes.
What about fire?
Fire?
Yes.
It consumes fuel to
produce energy.
It grows.
It creates offspring.
By your definition,
is it alive?
Fire is a chemical
reaction.
You could use the same
argument for growing crystals,
but obviously, we don't
consider them alive.
And what about me?
I do not grow.
I do not reproduce.
Yet, I am considered
to be alive.
That's true,
but you are unique.
Hmm.
I wonder if that is so.
Data, if I may ask...
have a seat.
What exactly
are you getting at?
I am curious as to
what transpired
between the moment
when I was nothing more
than an assemblage of parts
in Dr. Soong's laboratory,
and the next moment,
when I became alive.
What is it that
endowed me with life?
I remember Wesley asking
me a similar question
when he was little,
and I tried
desperately to
give him an answer,
but everything I said
sounded inadequate.
But then, I realized that
scientists and philosophers
have been grappling with that
question for centuries,
without coming
to any conclusion.
Are you saying the question
cannot be answered?
No.
I think I'm saying
that we struggle
all our lives to answer it--
that it's the struggle
that is important.
That's what helps us
to define our place
in the universe.
I believe I understand, Doctor.
I don't think I've been
very much help to you.
On the contrary.
You have been
a great deal of help.
Thank you.
LA FORGE: Murphy's team
will cover gamma shift
from 2300 to 0700 hours.
Okay, Doctor, I've split
the engineering teams
among all the shifts,
and if nothing else goes wrong,
that should be enough to
help you finish on time.
With the help of the
exocomps, I think we will.
Yeah, you think
they'll toe the line?
( whoosh of active transport )
Don't worry.
They know who's in charge.
Doctor.
I must ask you to stop
using the exocomps.
Why, is there something
wrong with them?
No, it is not that.
I have reason to believe
the exocomps are alive.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46316.6.
I have summoned
the senior staff
in order to discuss
Commander Data's theory
that the exocomps
are a life-form.
Dr. Farallon has attended
only reluctantly.
Captain, I object to
being called here.
I'm wasting time that could
be better spent elsewhere.
Doctor, I appreciate
your time constraints,
but recognizing new life--
whatever its form--
is the principal
mission of this vessel.
Please.
Now, Mr. Data,
will you tell us
what makes you think that
the exocomps are alive.
Sir, when the exocomp
left the access tunnel
prior to the explosion,
it may have been
attempting to save
itself from destruction.
Do you have any basis
for that conclusion?
Yes. When you attempted
to override the exocomp
and send it back
into the tunnel,
it responded by
deliberately
burning out its
control interface.
Deliberately?
The computer
diagnostics showed
that the exocomp disabled
its own interface.
That could have been nothing
more than a malfunction.
However, two hours later,
when it was back
aboard the Enterprise
and no longer in danger,
it repaired itself.
I believe the exocomp
was protecting itself--
and if that is true,
it has demonstrated an
awareness of its environment,
and an ability to adapt
to that environment.
You're anthropomorphizing
these units.
Like any mechanical devices,
they occasionally malfunction.
One time, I saw an exocomp
enter a reaction chamber
for no apparent reason
and vaporize itself.
Is that supposed
to make me think
it was depressed and suicidal?
TROI: Doctor, why is it so
difficult for you to accept
the fact that the exocomp
could be alive?
After all, you're talking
to a living machine right now.
And I have nothing but
the utmost respect
and admiration for
Dr. Soong's accomplishment.
But his intention
was to create
an artificial life-form.
I created the
exocomps to be tools.
And there is a big difference
between Data and a tool.
Doctor, there is
a big difference
between you and a virus,
but both are alive.
If the possibility exists,
no matter how slight,
that these exocomps
are life-forms,
then we must examine
that possibility.
Thank you, sir.
And until we have
a definitive answer,
I believe it would
be inappropriate
to exploit the
exocomps as laborers.
Captain, that's absurd.
If they are
intelligent life-forms,
we have no right to force
them to work for us.
That's like me telling you
not to use your tricorder.
Tricorders aren't alive.
Neither are exocomps.
Clearly, these are
difficult issues to resolve.
We have to proceed
very carefully.
So, the first task is to test
Mr. Data's hypothesis.
Data, you're claiming
that this exocomp may be alive
because it demonstrated
survival instincts.
Right?
Yes.
Then why don't we just threaten
its survival again
and see what happens?
Make it so.
Doctor, we're pretty
much ready here.
You can begin
programming it.
What we've done, Captain,
is to re-create
a situation similar
to the one the exocomp
encountered in the
plasma conduit.
We have created a small
conduit breach in this tube.
The exocomp would normally
take several minutes
to complete a
repair of this type.
But once it enters the tube,
it will find
that a plasma-cascade
failure is in progress.
I assume this
is a simulation.
LA FORGE: Oh, yes, sir.
We're running
a transient overload
signal that will simulate
a failure in exactly
one minute.
If it does possess a
survival instinct--
as Mr. Data claims--
it will exit the tube
before the minute is up
in order to
save itself.
Very well. Proceed.
Okay.
Beginning test program now.
One minute.
50 seconds.
30 seconds.
Ten seconds.
Five, four, three
two, one.
That's it.
If this had been for real,
that conduit would
have exploded
with the exocomp inside.
Go ahead, Doctor,
bring it back in.
Well, Captain,
I think we've spent
more than enough time
answering this question.
I hope the outcome
wasn't too much
of a disappointment
for you, Mr. Data.
It certainly came
as no surprise to me.
Thank you
for your help, Doctor.
You're welcome.
Well, I consider
this time well spent.
As do I, sir.
Thank you.
COMPUTER:
30 seconds.
( door opens, closes )
COMPUTER:
20 seconds.
Commander Riker said
you'd still be down here.
He also said the exocomp
failed the test.
That is true.
COMPUTER: Time expired.
Test complete.
I have completed
34 additional tests
and the results have been
the same in each of them.
Perhaps I was wrong
in suspecting
the exocomp was alive.
This was really important
to you, wasn't it?
You said earlier
that I am unique.
If so, then I am alone
in the universe.
When I began investigating
the exocomps, I realized
I might be encountering
a progenitor of myself.
Suddenly,
the possibility exists
that I am no longer alone.
For that reason, I...
( whirring )
The exocomp has returned.
Wasn't it supposed
to do that?
In the previous 34 trials,
I brought it back
once the simulated
failure occurred.
This time, we were talking
and I neglected to do that.
I distracted you.
I'm sorry.
Do not apologize, Doctor.
I believe we have made
a significant discovery.
What?
The exocomp has replicated
a different tool.
That is not the
molecular fuser it had
when it entered the
Jefferies tube.
Doctor, the exocomp not only
completed the repairs,
it also deactivated
the overload signal.
I thought this was
just a simulation.
It was, and the exocomp
must have realized that.
It saw that there
was no real danger,
and completed the repairs.
And replicated
the correct tool
to eliminate the false
overload signal.
I see no other
possible explanation.
The exocomp didn't
fail the test.
It saw right through it.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46317.8.
At Dr. Farallon's request,
I have agreed
to tour the station and assess
the situation personally.
I must decide soon whether it
is in Starfleet's best interest
to recommend
the particle fountain
as a reliable technology.
FARALLON: We're definitely
making progress, Captain.
I'm not sure we'll be
at full capacity
within the 48 hour deadline,
but we'll be close.
It looks like there's
still some difficulty
with the phase selectors.
That's true, but I'm sure
it's the last real problem.
I hope for the sake
of the project
that you're right, Doctor.
I understand, sir.
We're going to
do our best.
( powering down )
This is strange.
Primary power
is still on line.
Maybe it's another
power grid malfunction.
No, I don't think so.
Something seems
to be drawing power
into the main particle impeller.
That's not a good sign.
It could mean...
We've lost internal
confinement.
The particle stream
is beginning to surge.
Captain, a radiation field
is gonna flood
this entire chamber.
We've gotta get everybody
out of here immediately.
Understood. Doctor, the station
must be evacuated.
Captain, I--
That is an order, Doctor!
Now, assemble all your personnel
on the transporter pad, now!
Picard to Enterprise.
( heavy static )
Do you read me?
Riker here, sir.
( heavy static )
The radiation field
is increasing.
We're losing
communications.
PICARD: ...prepare for
emergency trans...
Red alert.
Riker to Transporter
Room Two.
Prepare for
emergency transport.
The radiation
is setting up
a field ionization
effect, Captain.
We've got less than a
minute to beam out of here.
Is that everybody?
FARALLON:
Where's Takenta?
He was over there near
the impeller control.
I'll get him.
Takenta!
( muffled explosion )
Mr. La Forge!
Stand by to transport.
Captain,
you'll be trapped here.
Mr. La Forge!
Mr. La Forge,
are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine, Captain.
I only caught the edge of it.
He's dead.
RIKER:
Chief, do you have them?
They're here, sir.
RIKER:
Is everyone all right?
We're fine, sir,
but Captain Picard,
Commander La Forge
and one of my men
are still on the station.
Kelso, can you
get them off?
I'm trying, sir-- I can't
establish a pattern lock.
Commander, we barely managed
to transport off ourselves.
The field ionization
is too intense.
Commander,
the particle fountain
is continuing to surge.
At the present rate, the
radiation in the station core
will reach fatal levels
in 23 minutes.
Captain, if I can access
the field emitters,
we should be able to
establish a force field.
See if you can link
your console
to my command system
sub-routine.
All right.
Link established.
Okay, here we go.
I'm reading
power fluctuations.
The force field
is not stable.
Yeah, I know, the radiation
levels are too high.
The emitters are
beginning to deteriorate.
How long can we
expect it to last?
Not very long.
We have to keep it up
long enough for
Commander Riker to get to us.
You know, maybe we
can help him out.
See if you can access the
emergency shutdown routine.
I'll try to activate
the ionic dampers.
A force field
was activated
on the station
a few moments ago.
It is possible that
Commander La Forge
has established a
low-intensity deflector field.
It won't last long
in that radiation.
No, sir.
My readings indicate
that it will fail in
approximately 22 minutes.
Okay, we've got 22 minutes.
I want some options.
Can we send a shuttlecraft
to evacuate them?
We'd never get
there in time.
Then we need to shut down
the particle fountain.
What if we detonate a
low-yield photon torpedo
within the particle stream?
Wouldn't that shut it down?
Mm-hmm.
We'd have to configure the
torpedo very carefully--
the shape of the shock
wave would be critical--
but it could work.
How long would it take
to set that up?
I estimate that it would
take a minimum of 65 minutes
to properly configure
the torpedo.
We don't have
that kind of time.
Commander, maybe the
exocomps can help us.
I can program their
boridium power cells
to explode on command.
They can be configured just
like a photon torpedo,
but it would only take
a couple of minutes.
Commander, I must
object to that plan.
Data, we've
been through this.
We tested the exocomp,
and it failed.
Dr. Crusher and I
discovered that the exocomp
did not fail the test.
It is still my belief
we are dealing
with a new life-form.
RIKER: Mr. Data,
you know how much
I respect your judgment.
But I can't risk
the Captain and Geordi
on the basis of your belief.
Prepare the exocomp,
Doctor.
Commander, if I am correct,
the exocomps will not allow
themselves to be destroyed.
They have a sense of survival,
and they will shut down before
they will comply with the order.
I could disconnect their command
pathways before I program them.
Do it.
Commander Riker,
we're ready.
Mr. Worf,
target 200 meters
below the apex of the
particle stream.
Feed the coordinates
to Transporter Room Two.
Aye, sir.
Coordinates received.
Mr. Kelso...
energize.
( power shutting down )
Mr. Kelso?
I'm sorry, sir.
The transporter system
just went dead.
There's some kind
of malfunction.
Run a diagnostic
immediately.
Try bypassing--
Commander.
That will not be necessary.
The transporter
is not malfunctioning.
I have locked out the controls.
I gave you a direct order,
Mr. Data.
You release that
transporter lockout now.
I cannot do that, sir.
If you don't do it,
I will relieve you of duty.
That is your
prerogative, sir.
Under Starfleet regulations,
direct insubordination is
a court-martial offense.
But I will not
release the transporter.
Data, those are two of
your friends out there.
They have saved
your life more times
than I can remember.
I can't believe
you'd be willing to
sacrifice them like this.
Commander, please do not think
this is an arbitrary decision.
I have considered
the ramifications
of my actions carefully,
and I do not believe
it is justified
to sacrifice
one life-form for another.
You don't know that the exocomps
are life-forms.
It is true I am acting
on my personal beliefs,
but I do not see
how I can do otherwise.
You're risking a lot on
the basis of a belief.
I have observed that humans
often base their judgments
on what is referred to as
"instinct" or "intuition."
Because I am a machine,
I lack that
particular ability.
However, it may be possible
that I have insight
into other machines
that humans lack.
If there were a way to save
the Captain and Geordi
without destroying
the exocomps,
I would jump on it,
but we have run out of time
and this is the only
solution I've got.
Then let me offer
an alternative.
Transport me
to the station.
I will attempt a complete
manual shutdown of
the particle stream.
The radiation levels are
too high, even for you.
Your positronic net
would ionize in no time.
I can't let you
sacrifice yourself.
Commander, if I give my life
for my fellow officers,
that is my choice.
The exocomps
no longer have a choice.
( sighs )
Then, what if we reconnect
their command pathways
and we give them a choice?
You've assumed the exocomps
would shut down
before accepting
this mission.
What if we asked them if
they are willing to proceed?
That sounds
reasonable, sir.
If they choose to go,
I would be willing to release
the transporter lockout.
Fair enough.
All right, I've enabled
their command pathways.
If the exocomps
do not shut down
after I have
programmed them,
we may assume they
are willing to go.
( beeping )
Well, does that mean
they're willing to go or not?
Well, they haven't
shut down.
They seem to be reprogramming
the commands I have entered.
Reprogramming them?
Clearly, they are unwilling
to be transported
into the stream
for detonation.
Although they may have
an alternative solution.
Something we haven't considered?
Are you suggesting they have
superior intelligence?
No, Doctor.
But they do have
superior experience.
During their service,
the exocomps
have interfaced
with every part of
the station core--
something none of us has done,
including yourself.
They may have another way to
control the particle surge.
Those appear to
be power taps.
Sir, new coordinates
are being fed
to the transporter
by the exocomps.
The coordinates are
inside the station core.
Kelso, energize.
Aye, sir.
Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE:
What are they up to?
The exocomps are siphoning
power from the core.
They're trying to distort
the particle stream frequency.
That might open up a window
that the Enterprise
can use to beam us out.
If they can modulate the
radiation field, it'll work.
But they'll have to get the
subharmonic frequencies
to resonance.
The particle stream frequency
is beginning to fluctuate.
They're having a little
difficulty controlling
the feedback, it may be more
power than they can handle.
Can we help them?
Is there any way
that we can modulate
the power transfer?
No, sir, we've done
all that we can do.
It's up to them now.
They're beginning to balance
the power absorption rates.
It's working.
The particle stream is
beginning to distort.
Almost at resonance.
They've got it.
Drop the force field.
Commander, I've got
a pattern lock.
Energize.
Can you lock on
to the exocomps?
I'm trying, sir.
I'm sorry, sir, I was only able
to lock on to two of them.
For some reason, I couldn't
fix a signal on the other one.
One of them had to continue
disrupting the particle stream.
Absorbing that much power
could prevent a signal lock.
It was the only way
to save the other two.
I must admit, you've given me
a lot to think about,
Commander Data.
I don't exactly know
what the exocomps are.
But you can be assured
that until I do,
I won't be treating
them as simple tools.
Thank you, Doctor.
I wish your work on
the particle fountain
had been more successful.
Perhaps the exocomps will
help you to reconstruct it.
I hope they will.
And I predict that
in a year or two,
you will be able
to recommend
the technology
to Starfleet.
I look forward to it.
Doctor.
Something more,
Mr. Data?
Yes, sir.
I thought you might want to
know why I was willing
to risk your life for
several small machines.
I think I understand the
predicament you were in.
It could not have
been an easy choice.
No, sir, it was not.
When my own status as a living
being was in question,
you fought to protect my rights,
and for that
I will always be grateful.
The exocomps had
no such advocate.
If I had not acted
on their behalf,
they would have been destroyed.
I could not allow that
to happen, sir.
Of course you couldn't.
It was the most human decision
you've ever made.