Captain's Log,
Stardate 46357.4.
We have rendezvoused
with the starship Cairo
near the Cardassian border
for an urgent meeting
with Vice-Admiral Nechayev.
( door chimes )
Come.
May I present
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Admiral,
welcome on board.
Thank you.
That'll be all,
Commander.
Can I get you
some coffee, tea?
Thank you, no, Captain.
I'm afraid there's no time
for the usual pleasantries.
I'm here to relieve you
of command of the Enterprise.
(Picard)
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
The Cardassian forces
which were recently withdrawn
from the Bajoran sector
have been redeployed
along the Federation border.
They have mobilized
three divisions of ground troops
and their subspace
communications
have been increased by 50%.
We believe that
they're preparing
for an incursion
into Federation space.
Are the Cardassians
ready for a war?
I didn't say "war," Commander.
I said "incursion."
Our intelligence
reports suggest
that they'll try to seize
one of the disputed systems
along the border.
We think they're gambling
that the Federation
won't actually go to war
over one system.
Will we?
I hope we won't need
to make that decision.
We have decided
to send the Enterprise
to meet with a Cardassian
representative
and open talks.
We're hoping that the presence
of the Federation flagship
on the border will send
a message to their leadership
about just how seriously
we view this situation.
Where is Captain Picard?
The captain,
your chief medical officer,
and security chief
have been reassigned.
That's all I can tell you
for now.
Do any of you know
Edward Jellico?
He is the commanding officer
of the Cairo.
I've heard of him, I don't know
that any of us have ever...
I'm giving
him command
of the Enterprise
this afternoon.
Captain Jellico
helped to negotiate
the original armistice
two years ago,
and I believe he's
the most qualified person
to lead this mission.
The change of command
will take place at 1300 hours.
Thank you.
Admiral,
with all due respect...
it's not necessary
to give Captain Jellico
command of the Enterprise
just to conduct
a negotiation.
I disagree.
The Enterprise will be
in a dangerous situation,
and I want someone
on the Bridge
who has a great
deal of experience
with the Cardassians.
No offense, Commander,
but that's not you.
MAN:
Halt!
PICARD:
Computer, freeze program.
You were five seconds
slower that time.
You increased the
difficulty level, sir.
Mr. Worf, it's going
to be far more difficult
where we're going.
Which is where, exactly?
I'm sorry,
I can't tell you that yet.
WORF:
It would be helpful
to know something
about our mission.
Mr. Worf, I have my orders.
I'm sure you understand that.
Now, Doctor, this deflector
wasn't set properly.
It must be positioned
so that the emitter array
blocks the entire passageway
or it's useless.
Sorry. I was concentrating
on getting away
from the last Cardassian.
Or maybe it was
the falling rocks?
I understand this is difficult.
All I can do
is ask you to trust me.
All right,
let's do it again.
All right, Mr. Worf
I want you to time
the doctor and me
through that first tunnel,
and this time
we're going to pick up
those five seconds.
Welcome aboard, sir.
I'm commander...
William T. Riker,
class of '57.
Graduated eighth
in his class.
I'm looking forward
to serving with
you, Commander.
Thank you,
and I, you.
I'm sure this
change in command
has taken everyone
a little by surprise.
Well... yes, sir.
It caught me
by surprise, too.
I must admit,
I miss the Cairo already,
but a galaxy-class ship,
that's something special.
I can understand
why you turned down
a ship of your own
to remain aboard.
Yes, sir.
How many duty watches
does the crew stand?
We have a standard
three-shift rotation.
I'd like to change that
to four starting tonight.
I'd also like to examine
the duty roster
and the crew evaluations
as soon as possible.
I want readiness reports
from each department head
by 1400 hours
and a meeting
of the senior staff at 1500.
Do you prefer Will
or William?
Um, Will sir.
Where are my quarters, Will?
We have you assigned
to cabin 735...
Deck seven,
I'll see you at 1300 hours.
( buzz of conversation )
Attention to orders!
"To Captain Jean-Luc Picard
"Commanding Officer,
USS Enterprise.
"Stardate 46358.1.
"You are hereby
requested and required
"to relinquish command
of your vessel
"to Captain Edward Jellico
"Commanding Officer,
USS Cairo
"as of this date.
"Signed, Vice-Admiral
Alynna Nechayev
Starfleet Command."
Computer, transfer
all command codes
to Captain Edward Jellico.
Voice authorization:
Picard-delta-five.
COMPUTER:
Transfer complete.
USS Enterprise
now under command
of Captain Edward Jellico.
I relieve you, sir.
I stand relieved.
Dismissed.
I wonder how permanent
this is going to be.
I don't know.
They don't usually
go through the ceremony
if it's just a
temporary assignment.
Sore?
Oh... sore doesn't
begin to describe it.
I know.
I wish I could talk about it.
Most of the
secondary systems
were changed
at the last overhaul.
I don't think they'll
give you any problem
but you might
want to check out
the port lateral...
I'll take care of the
Enterprise, Jean-Luc.
You don't have
to mother me.
Uh...
How's your team shaping up?
Very well...
but I would prefer more
recent intelligence
on the exact layout
of the installation.
The most current information
that we have is two years old.
Two years?
I don't know how Nechayev
ever talked you into this.
She gave me no choice.
Well, maybe there's something
we can do to help.
We'll launch a class-5 probe
just before we reach the border.
You could pick up the telemetry
aboard the shuttle.
Now that would be
extremely helpful.
Will?
Captain.
I believe we're
scheduled to arrive
at the Cardassian border
during delta shift.
Please inform
the delta tactical officer
that I want to launch
a class-5 probe
just before
we drop out of warp.
I was actually going to talk
to you about delta shift
a little later, sir.
Right now, gamma shift will be
on duty when we arrive
and I will tell
Lieutenant McDowell
about the probe.
Is there a problem
with delta shift, Will?
There is no
delta shift yet, sir.
I have spoken
to the department heads
about changing from
three shifts to four
and they assure me
it's going to cause
a significant
personnel problems.
So you have not changed
the watch rotation?
I was going to
explain this to you
after the ceremony, sir.
You will tell the department
heads that as of now
the Enterprise is
on a four-shift rotation.
I don't want to talk about it.
Get it done.
Now that means that delta shift
will be due to come on duty
in two hours.
I expect you
to have it fully manned
and ready when it does.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
If you'll excuse me, sir.
Captain.
( sighs )
He was your first officer
for five years.
One of the finest
officers
that I have ever
served with.
Of course he is,
Jean-Luc.
I'm sure it'll all work out.
( sighs )
JELLICO:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46358.2.
The Enterprise is on course
for a rendezvous
with the Cardassian ship
Reklar.
Fortunately, I still have time
to prepare the ship and crew
for the task ahead.
I want you to install a bypass
between the main phaser array
and the secondary generators.
I also want to run
the main deflector pathway
through the warp power grid
and the auxiliary conduits
through the lateral relays.
Now, you may have to reconfigure
the transfer interface.
Sir, the transfer interface
was not designed
for that configuration.
It will take seven hours
to make those changes.
Sir, you may not be aware
that our normal interface
already routes auxiliary power
through three separate relays.
I'm aware
of your current design system.
It's not good enough.
If these negotiations fail
we could find ourselves
in a war zone
and if that happens
I want to be loaded for bear.
I'll get right on it.
Good.
Now, these stations
should be devoted
to damage-control
and weapons status from now on.
See that they're manned
at all times.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Data,
how long before we reach
the rendezvous point?
We will arrive
in 51 hours, 32 minutes, sir.
Schedule four battle drills
one for each shift.
Run a series
of simulated attacks
from a Cardassian squadron.
I want you to conduct
the exercises personally, Will.
Get it done.
Oh...
and get that fish
out of the Ready Room.
Data, you're with me.
The power transfer levels
need to be upgraded by 20%.
The efficiency
of your warp coils
is also unsatisfactory.
Coil efficiency is
well within
specifications, Captain.
I'm not interested
in the specs, Geordi.
The efficiency needs to be
raised by at least 15%.
15 percent?
That is
an attainable goal,
but it will require
realigning the warp coil
and taking the secondary
distribution grid off-line.
Very good, Data.
That's exactly what
I want you to do.
If we take this grid off-line,
we're going to have to shut down
Exobiology, the Astrophysics Lab
and Geological Research.
We're not on
a research mission.
Get it done...
in two days.
I believe that is also
an attainable goal.
If we utilize the entire
Engineering Department
there should be
sufficient manpower available
to complete the task.
Sure, if everybody works around
the clock for the next two days.
Then you'd better
get to it, Geordi.
Looks like you have
some work to do.
Data.
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Yes?
May I speak with
you, Captain?
Deanna, come in, come in.
The latest masterpieces
from my son.
It's an elephant...
I think.
Definitely an elephant.
I'm glad you're here.
I'd like to go over
the duty roster with you.
I'd be happy to,
but, first
I'd like to talk about
how the change in command
is affecting the crew.
I've noticed some resistance.
I wouldn't call it
resistance.
More like... uncertainty.
Most of them had served
under Captain Picard
for several years.
They knew him and they knew
what he expected.
Now they're being asked
to adjust to a new captain
and a new way of doing things,
and they're uncertain
how to react.
I see your point.
This all could be
very unsettling to them.
And to you.
Perhaps everyone
just needs time.
Time for you to get to know
and trust the crew
and time for them
to understand how you
want things done.
I'm glad you brought this
to my attention, Deanna.
Unfortunately, I don't have time
for a honeymoon with the crew.
You've clearly
given this a lot
of thought,
so I'd like you to take charge
of the morale situation.
Please see to it
that they make the adjustment
to the new routine
quickly and easily.
Oh, I have a meeting
with the new security chief
in five minutes,
so the duty roster
will have to wait.
Thank you, Counselor.
By the way...
I prefer a certain...
formality on the Bridge.
I'd appreciate it
if you wore a standard uniform
when you're on duty.
Of course, sir.
LA FORGE:
Commander, he's asked me
to completely reroute
half the power systems
on this ship,
change every duty roster
realign the warp coils
in two days,
and now he's transferred
a third of my crew to security.
If it makes you feel any
better, you're not alone.
Captain Jellico
has made major changes
in every department
on the ship.
Yeah, well, I don't
mind making changes,
and I don't mind hard work,
but the man isn't giving me
the time I need to do the work.
Somebody's got to get him
to listen to reason.
It's not going to be me.
He's made that
abundantly clear.
Well, then can I make
a suggestion?
Talk to Captain Picard.
Maybe he can
do something.
We just need
a little time.
All right.
( door chimes )
Come.
You all right, sir?
Yes, I am,
but the last time
I had to train like this
was for the Academy marathon
but... I'm managing.
What can I do for you?
It's nothing urgent.
I'm sorry
I bothered you.
Good night.
( sighs )
My orders are
to maintain radio silence
until we've completed
the mission.
Well, the Enterprise
will be monitoring
your channel
just in case you do need
to transmit a signal.
RIKER:
Bridge to Captain Jellico.
We've arrived at the shuttle
departure coordinates.
Did you launch
the probe I requested?
Yes, sir. I wasn't aware
you wanted to be informed.
Thank you.
Jellico out.
( muttering ):
I can see why he's still
only a first officer.
Captain, I would just like you
to know that Commander Riker...
I've read your
reports, Jean-Luc.
I know you think
highly of him.
It's not just my opinion.
He's been decorated
by Starfleet Command five times.
He's been offered his own ship
more than once.
I think if you just
gave him a chance
you would find him
an outstanding officer.
Jean-Luc, let's be
candid for a moment.
The Cardassians aren't
going to listen to reason
and the Federation isn't going
to give in to their demands,
and the chances are you
won't be coming back
from this mission
of yours.
I want this ship
ready for action,
and I don't have time
to give Will Riker
or anyone else a "chance."
And forgive me for being blunt,
but the Enterprise is mine now.
Well... here's hoping
you beat the odds.
Good hunting.
Thank you.
Jean-Luc...
I believe this is yours.
Shuttlecraft Feynman
to Enterprise.
We have cleared
the shuttle bay.
RIKER:
Acknowledged, Feynman.
Good luck.
Thank you, Enterprise.
Well...
now that we're underway
I can tell you
about our mission.
Starfleet intelligence
believes that the Cardassians
are developing
a metagenic weapon.
Oh, my God.
I am not familiar
with metagenics.
They're genetically
engineered viruses
that are designed to destroy
entire ecosystems.
When metagenic toxins
are released
into a planet's atmosphere
they immediately
begin to mutate.
They seek out and destroy
all forms of DNA they encounter.
In a few days
everything is dead.
In a month
the metagenic agent itself
breaks down
and dissipates completely
leaving every city, every road,
every piece of equipment
perfectly intact.
Leaving the planet safe
to be conquered.
Wouldn't using
such a weapon
pose as great a risk
to the attacker
as to the target?
That's why metagenics
and other biological weapons
were outlawed years ago.
Even the Romulans
have abided with
those agreements.
Starfleet intelligence
believes that the Cardassians
are developing
a new delivery system
one that would protect them
from accidental exposure
to the toxin.
They believe
that the Cardassians
are testing a way of launching
dormant metagenic material
on a subspace carrier wave.
So they could activate
the toxins after the launch
thereby preventing
any accidental exposure.
Mm-hmm.
And because the subspace wave
would appear simply
as background radiation
no one would realize
what was happening
until it was too late.
Now, for the past
few weeks
theta-band
subspace emissions
have been detected
coming from Celtris III.
These emissions
may indicate
that a metagenic delivery system
is in operation.
What do we know
about Celtris III?
Very little.
It was thought to be uninhabited
until these emissions
were detected.
Starfleet believes
that the Cardassians
may have a secret research lab
located somewhere
below the planet's surface.
Our orders are to penetrate
this Celtris III installation
and determine if the Cardassians
are actually building
a metagenic weapon.
And if they are?
Destroy it...
at any cost.
When I was
on the Stargazer
we conducted extensive tests
using theta-band carrier waves.
One of the reasons I was
selected for this mission
is my familiarity
with the methods used
for generating them.
Mr. Worf, your presence
here is obvious.
Doctor, your job will be
to locate and to destroy
any biotoxins
we may find.
Celtris III
is in Cardassian space.
How will we get there
undetected?
I... know a way of acquiring
some discreet transport.
Mr. Worf, set a course
for Torman V.
( conversation and laughter )
If he doesn't pay up
I know three
large Ferengi
who will not be
so forgiving.
( cackling )
I didn't do it.
We're not accusing you
of anything.
What do you want then?
We're looking
for Daimon Solok.
Why?
We have a business
proposition to discuss.
Solok is a very busy,
very important man.
He isn't here.
But I could relay a message.
Good.
Please, will you
tell Daimon Solok
that we're interested
in transportation...
( softly ):
to Celtris III?
That's a Cardassian planet.
Uh-huh.
Now, we understand
that Daimon Solok
runs cargo there
from time to time.
Solok is no smuggler.
Yes, but if Solok were
to go to Celtris III
for legitimate reasons
we would be interested
in quietly booking passage
for the journey.
I don't think
he would be interested
in dealing
with Federation spies.
You know...
I heard that Solok
was quite a man.
Why... yes.
He is a...
extraordinary man.
That's why we came here
because only Solok
could help us...
but I guess there
are some things
even Solok can't do.
It's too bad.
Because...
if he could,
I would be...
very...
Yes?
Grateful.
When do you
want to leave?
( tricorder beeping )
Beverly, make sure
that your tricorder
is keeping a precise
map of the route.
It would be very easy
to get lost in here.
Right.
( louder, rapid beeping )
I'm picking up
some subspace signals
but I can't seem
to get a lock on them.
That's typical
of theta-band emissions.
You have to compress
the detection bandwidth
in order to determine
the fix.
The source emission is 500
meters east of here, and...
700 meters below.
( screeching )
It's all right.
They're called lynars.
They're a kind of Celtran bat.
They're harmless.
Bats?
You're not afraid of bats,
are you, Worf?
Of course not.
RIKER:
First Officer's Log
supplemental.
We have rendezvoused with
the Cardassian ship Reklar
to begin diplomatic talks
designed to ease tensions
along the border.
Gul Lemec has arrived.
He's waiting for you
in the Observation Lounge.
Very good.
I'll be in my Ready Room.
( door chimes )
Yes?
Captain, I think there's been
a slight miscommunication.
Did you want to meet
with Gul Lemec in here?
No, the Observation Lounge
is appropriate.
I see.
Lemec is a Cardassian
and Cardassians
are like timber wolves--
predators--
bold in large numbers,
cautious by themselves,
and with an instinctive need
to establish a dominant position
in any social gathering.
So you're trying to establish
a dominant position
by making him wait for you.
The trouble with wolves
is that sometimes in the fight
for dominance
one of them ends up dead.
In that case, the trick is
to be the wolf that's
still standing at the end.
The floor is over
500 meters down from here.
There doesn't seem to be
a way around.
We'll have to rappel
from here.
This is sheer granite.
We'll have to use fusing pitons.
We could try to find
another way down.
Unfortunately, that would take
several hours.
We don't have the time.
You're not afraid of heights
are you, Doctor?
Of course not.
Now, remember to control
your descent.
Don't get the lines tangled.
I'll remember.
All right?
What is going on?
I've been waiting here
for over an hour...
I'm Captain Jellico.
I believe you know
Commander Riker
and this is Lieutenant
Commander Troi.
Let's get to it,
shall we?
This treatment
is a deliberate insult
to the Cardassian Union.
I have been kept waiting
here for over an hour.
Then I'm sure
you're ready to talk.
I did not agree
to allow others
into this meeting.
If it alarms you,
I can ask them to leave.
I am not alarmed,
but we did not...
A great many people
are depending
on our efforts here, Gul Lemec.
We don't need to quibble
over minutiae.
I have come to negotiate
a Federation withdrawal
from the borders
not to be dictated to
by some mere captain.
I can see you're not serious
about these talks.
If the Cardassian Union
truly wishes to discuss peace
they can send someone
who can negotiate
in a civilized manner.
Captain on the Bridge.
Let him stew
for a few minutes.
Then go in and tell him
that you've convinced me
to meet with him
one more time.
Tell him I'm a loose cannon
and that he needs to be
more reasonable
because I'm such
an unreasonable man.
Lemec will want to bring
his own aides on board.
Pretend to be worried
that I'll object, and then
give grudging permission
for two aides, no more.
Understood?
Aye, sir.
Well, I'll say
this for him--
he's sure of himself.
No, he's not.
The installation should be
about 300 meters... this way.
I don't suppose
we'll be able
to find another way
to get back up there.
I doubt it.
That's what I thought.
Hmm...
There's a lava tube beyond here
that runs for 75 meters.
Then it connects
with another chamber.
We need to get through here.
This tube opens up
beyond this crack.
If we could widen
the opening
then we should be able
to crawl through.
Mr. Worf?
A phaser set at level 16
should suffice.
Make it so.
Well done, Mr. Worf.
Gul Lemec.
A pleasure.
May I present my aides
Glinn Corak and Glinn Tajor.
Welcome aboard.
For the past three weeks
you've been massing troops
in staging areas
assembling strike forces
and pulling ships
from their normal patrols.
We will not stand for this
clearly provocative
behavior.
I see the Federation
spy network
has again provided you
with faulty information.
We are conducting
routine training operations
nothing more.
Then I'm sure you won't mind
if we send a few starships
into this sector
for our own...
training operations.
Your fleet deployments
do not concern us.
However, we are very concerned
with your refusal to vacate
those territories
along the border
which are clearly Cardassian.
You gave up your claims
on those territories
when you signed the armistice.
You couldn't take those worlds
by force, so you
want us to give them
to you at the bargaining table.
Captain, please.
We should
listen to them.
Gul Lemec, as you know
the systems
are still under negotiation
by the terms of the treaty.
Negotiations which we have
pursued in good faith.
Unfortunately, the Federation
has not been as forthcoming.
So, to speed up the process,
you are preparing for war.
We are preparing
to defend ourselves.
The Federation
will not start a war.
That has always been
your position.
However, I have heard reports
that a small team
from the Federation
has already been sent
into our territory.
Of course, I
don't believe it.
Such an attempt
would almost certainly fail
and even if it succeeded,
it would trigger
a very serious response
on our part.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Then there's no need for worry.
A brief recess
would seem to be in order.
Very well.
Where is Captain Picard?
Reassigned.
Well, I hope his new assignment
is not too dangerous.
It would be a shame
if something were to happen
to such a, uh...
such a noted officer.
Yes...
it would.
PICARD:
Only a few more meters.
Beverly, get
out of there!
Beverly!
WORF:
I have her.
( Crusher coughing )
Are you all right?
I think so.
Next time, you
try bringing up the rear.
We're nearly there.
Can you continue?
PICARD:
It looks like
a maintenance hatch
to the installation.
I'm picking up three
proximity sensors around it.
Sensor echo is established,
but the false image
will only last a few minutes.
The hatch is
magnetically sealed,
but I believe
I can bypass it.
I can't get a scan from the
other side of the hatch.
It's been shielded.
We have no choice.
Remember, aim low
and fire in short,
controlled bursts.
Ready.
Now.
CRUSHER:
There's no one here.
There's no lab.
It's a trap. Come on!
Captain!
( gasping )
Let's go.
The captain!
No. There are
five more of them
heading this way
from another tunnel.
Come on.
Now!
Captain on the Bridge.
What have you got, Will?
I'm not sure.
We're picking up
a lot of coded messages
from a Cardassian planet
near the border.
Which planet?
Celtris III.
Can you detect
any theta-band
subspace emissions
coming from Celtris?
There are some
residual traces.
It seems that there
were emissions
up until a few minutes ago.
( sighs )
Open a secure channel
to Admiral Nechayev.
Priority two.
Put it through
to my Ready Room.
Aye, sir.
Captain?
Those emissions you were
so concerned about
have just stopped.
I'd say one way or another
our friends
have finished their task.
Have you heard
from our friends?
No.
Let me know if you do.
I would very much like
to see them again.
So would I, Admiral.
A challenge.
You should prove
an interesting challenge.
Possibly the most interesting
to come through that door
in many years.
What do you want?
Why, you, of course.
Picard...
Jean-Luc.
Serial number...
SP-937-215.
Son of Maurice
and Yvette Picard.
Born in La Barre, France.
Formerly, captain
of the Stargazer
where you conducted
extensive studies
on theta-band subspace
carrier waves.
Don't look so surprised.
How could we have
designed a lure
for the captain
of the Federation flagship
unless we knew something
about his background?
So you concocted
an elaborate ruse
to bring me here.
Why?
In this room,
you do not ask questions.
I ask them.
You answer.
If I am not satisfied
with your answers
you will die.