Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
"You are hereby requested
and required
"to relinquish command
of your vessel
"to captain Edward Jellico,
Commanding Officer
USS Cairo, as of this date."
I want this ship
ready for action
and I don't have time
to give Will Riker,
or anyone else a "chance."
And forgive me
for being blunt
but the Enterprise is mine now.
Our orders are to penetrate
the Celtris III
installation.
It's a trap! Come on!
Let's go.
The captain!
No. There are
five more of them
heading this way
from another tunnel.
You should prove
an interesting challenge.
Possibly the most interesting
to come through that door
in many years.
What do you want?
Why, you, of course.
And now, the conclusion.
Your place
of birth?
( detached monotone ):
La Barre, France.
Mother's name?
Yvette Gessard.
He's ready.
Keep the serum
at that level.
What is your
current assignment?
Special operations
on Celtris III.
What is your mission
on Celtris III?
To seek and destroy
a metagenic weapon.
How many others
were part of this mission?
Two.
Name and rank?
Chief Medical Officer
Beverly Crusher.
Lieutenant Worf.
What are the Federation's
defense plans for Minos Korva?
I don't know.
Increase the level
slightly to .31.
Let's begin again,
shall we?
Name?
Picard, Jean-Luc.
Place of birth?
La Barre, France.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
JELLICO:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46360.8.
The negotiations
with the Cardassians
have made little progress.
I believe
a military confrontation
may be unavoidable.
Gul Lemec, I assure you
that what the Federation wants
above all,
is the preservation of peace.
Then, how do you
explain the fact
that a Federation team
launched an unprovoked assault
on Cardassian territory
less than 14 hours ago?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Then let me explain.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard,
Lieutenant Worf,
and Dr. Beverly Crusher
landed on Celtris III
attacked one of our outposts
in a brutal assault
and killed over
55 men, women
and children.
What evidence
do you have of that?
We have all the
evidence we need.
We have Captain Picard.
Is he alive?
The Cardassian Union
has yet to decide
how it will respond
to this latest provocation,
but rest assured...
we will respond.
Is there any truth
in what he's saying?
Captain Picard
and the others
were sent
to investigate reports
of a metagenic weapon
on Celtris III.
It's possible that they
may have been captured,
but if they did escape
they'll head for
the Lyshan system.
The Enterprise is supposed to
meet them there in eight hours.
Will, I want you to take
a shuttlecraft
and head
for the rendezvous point.
The Enterprise
will have to remain here
until the endgame
with Gul Lemec is played out.
Aye, sir.
Captain Picard.
I demand to see
a neutral representative
as required by
the Federation-Cardassian
peace treaty.
We have already sent a message
to Tohvun III--
the nearest
neutral planet.
They assure us
they will dispatch
someone immediately.
Will you allow me
to remove your restraints?
( beeping, clicking )
I understand that you are
a student of archaeology.
Did you know
that Cardassia boasts
some of the most ancient
and splendid ruins
in the entire galaxy?
I know that the burial vaults
of the first
Hebitian civilization
are said to be magnificent.
Apparently, when they
were first unearthed
200 years ago, they were.
The burial vaults contained
unimaginably beautiful
artifacts made of jevonite--
a rare, breathtaking stone--
but most
of those objects are gone.
What happened to them?
What happens
to impoverished societies--
the tombs were plundered,
priceless treasures stolen.
A few were preserved in museums
but even those
were eventually sold
in order to pay
for our war efforts.
That war cost you hundreds
of thousands of lives.
It depleted your food supplies
left your population
weakened and miserable
and yet you risk another war.
Let's not waste time arguing
about issues we cannot resolve.
Would you care to tour
the Hebitian burial vaults?
What I would like
is to be returned to my ship.
My dear Captain,
you are a criminal.
You've been apprehended
invading one of our
secret facilities.
The least that will happen
is for you to stand trial
and be punished.
But I'm offering you
the opportunity
for that experience to be...
civilized.
What is the price
of that opportunity?
Cooperation.
We need to know
the Federation's
defense strategy
for Minos Korva.
You've injected me with drugs.
Surely, you must realize
that I've already answered
truthfully
every question you've put to me.
Captain, we have gone to great
lengths to lure you here
because we know that,
in the event of an invasion
the Enterprise will be
the command ship for the sector
encompassing
Minos Korva.
Then, it seems you have
more knowledge of
the situation than I.
Wasted energy, Captain.
You might come to wish
you hadn't expended it
in such a futile effort.
Torture is expressly forbidden
under the terms
of the Seldonis IV Convention
governing the treatment
of prisoners of war!
Are you in good health?
Do you have any
physical ailments
I should know about?
Beautiful, isn't it?
The stone is jevonite,
and now you know why
it is so highly prized.
From this point on
you will enjoy
no privilege of rank
no privileges of person.
From now on, I will refer
to you only as "human."
You have no other identity.
( beep )
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
I have returned
from the rendezvous point
in the Lyshan system
with Dr. Crusher
and Lieutenant Worf.
Captain Picard's fate
is still unknown.
There was no chance
to go back
for the captain.
We barely made it back
to the Ferengi cargo ship
ourselves.
You were smart
not to try.
I don't feel so smart.
Get some rest, Doctor.
Will.
I want Geordi to
analyze the readings
from Beverly's tricorder.
Tell him to scrutinize
every detail
of those caverns
on Celtris III.
Aye, sir.
Request permission to begin
planning a rescue operation.
I know you were
close to him, Will,
but we don't even know
if he's still alive.
Under the circumstances
a rescue mission
would be foolhardy.
Shouldn't we assume
that he is alive
until it's been
proved otherwise?
We cannot just abandon him.
He's gone.
I'm sorry, Will, but you're
going to have to accept that.
I want those tricorder readings
analyzed by 1400 hours.
Yes, sir.
Good morning.
I trust you slept well.
( panting )
Thirsty?
I would imagine so.
Well...
it's time to move on.
I told you all that I know.
Yes, I'm sure you have.
How many lights
do you see there?
I see four lights.
No.
There are five.
Are you quite sure?
There are four lights.
Perhaps you're aware
of the incision in your chest.
While you were under
the influence of our drugs
you were implanted
with a small device.
It's a remarkable invention.
By entering commands
in this PADD
I can produce pain
in any part of your body--
at various levels
of severity.
Forgive me.
I don't enjoy this,
but I must demonstrate.
It will make everything clearer.
( gasps in pain )
Surprising, isn't it?
Most people feel at first they
can steel themselves against it,
but they're
completely unprepared
for the intensity of the pain.
That was the lowest
possible setting.
I know nothing
about Minos Korva.
But I've told you
that I believe you.
I didn't ask you
about Minos Korva.
I asked how many
lights you see.
There are four lights.
I don't understand
how you can be so mistaken.
( intense groans )
What is your
current assignment?
Special operations
on Celtris III.
Do you have anything to say?
Captain Picard was not
acting under my orders.
And if we wish to execute him?
Under the terms
of the Seldonis Convention,
Captain Picard...
The Seldonis Convention
applies to prisoners of war.
Which means you
would have to acknowledge
that he was captured
during a mission
authorized by the Federation.
Are you willing to make
such an admission?
No.
Then, he will be treated
as a terrorist.
It's not my concern.
There is, of course,
an alternative.
JELLICO:
I'm listening.
If the Federation agreed
to a complete and immediate
withdrawal from this sector
then we would be... disposed
to release Captain Picard
and forget about this incident.
I'll have to discuss this
with my superiors.
Of course.
You have seven hours.
What are you going to do?
Send a message
to Admiral Nechayev.
I recommend that she reject
Lemec's proposal
and deploy additional
starships along the border.
What about
Captain Picard?
I'm not suggesting you
trade an entire star system
for one man's life,
but you've got
to acknowledge
that these were
Federation orders
and that he is
a prisoner of war.
No.
He will have
the protection
of the Seldonis Convention.
That would play right
into Gul Lemec's hand.
He's just waiting for some
sign of weakness on our part
before he starts
making more demands.
I can't believe you're
willing to sacrifice
Captain Picard's life
as a negotiation tactic.
Will, Captain,
we're all concerned about...
Are you questioning
my judgment, Commander?
As first officer,
it is my responsibility
to point out any actions
that may be mistakes
by a commanding officer, sir.
Then, maybe it's time
you found other
responsibilities.
You're relieved.
Don't...
make me confine you
to quarters as well.
Sir.
They went to a
lot of trouble
to lure a Federation
team to that planet.
Why?
It is possible
the Cardassians
were specifically interested
in capturing Captain Picard.
Why do you say that?
The metagenic weapon
they were supposedly developing
used a theta-band
subspace delivery system.
Captain Picard is one
of only three Starfleet captains
with extensive experience
in theta-band devices.
The other two
are no longer in Starfleet.
So they tailored a fake
weapon to lure Picard.
But why?
They must have known
we'd change all his access codes
and security protocols.
Maybe they were interested
in something that he did
in the past--
something that happened while he
was captain of the Enterprise.
Or something he was going to do
in the future.
In case of a Cardassian attack
the Enterprise will be assigned
as command ship for this sector.
If the Cardassians
got wind of that...
They might have assumed
that captain Picard would know
those defense plans.
If your theory is correct,
the Cardassians may be planning
an attack somewhere
in this sector.
The question is where.
Geordi, I want you
to conduct a discreet scan
of Gul Lemec's ship.
Look for anything unusual--
anything that might indicate
where they've been lately.
Aye, sir.
I want you to be very careful
with your wompat
from now on,
Jil Orra.
Now that she's separated
from her mother
she depends on you.
I will, Father.
Do humans have
mothers and fathers?
Yes...
but human mothers
and fathers
don't love their children
as we do.
They're not the same
as we are.
Will you read
to me tonight?
Yes, of course, I will.
I'll see you later.
( squeaking )
( door closes )
Your daughter is lovely.
Yes, I think so.
And unusually bright.
It's amazing,
isn't it--
the way they're able
to sneak into your heart?
I must admit
I was completely unprepared
for the power
she had over me...
from the moment she was born.
I am surprised that...
you let her come in here.
Why?
To expose a child to... this--
to someone
who is suffering.
To see that
it is you
that inflict that suffering.
From the time,
Jil Orra could crawl
she's been taught about
the enemies of the Cardassians
and that enemies
deserve their fates.
When children learn
to devalue others
they can devalue anyone,
including their parents.
What a blind,
narrow view you have.
What an arrogant man you are.
What do you know
of Cardassian history?
I know that once you
were a peaceful people
with a rich spiritual life.
And what did peace
and spirituality get us?
People starved
by the millions.
Bodies went unburied.
Disease was rampant.
The suffering
was unimaginable.
Since the military
took over
hundreds of thousands
more have died.
But we are feeding the people.
We acquired territory
during the wars.
We developed new resources.
We initiated
a rebuilding program.
We have mandated
agricultural programs.
That... is what the military
has done for Cardassia.
And because of that
my daughter will never
worry about going hungry.
Her belly may be full
but her spirit will be empty.
Shall we begin again?
How many lights
are there?
What lights?
( agonized groaning )
LA FORGE:
It looks like they had
some minor hull degradation
along their warp nacelles.
The distribution pattern
indicates a recent exposure
to a molecular dispersion field.
Where could they have run
into a dispersion field?
The McAllister C-5 Nebula
is just across the border.
It's approximately
seven light years
from Federation space.
Could there be
Cardassian ships
inside the McAllister Nebula?
Well, it's possible,
but they wouldn't be able
to stay in there
for very long.
The particle flux
from the nebula
would begin to break
down a ship's hull
just after 72 hours.
Is there a Federation system
near the McAllister Nebula
that might interest
the Cardassians?
Minos Korva is just 11 light
years from the nebula
and the Cardassians tried
to annex it during the war.
Data, I want to be
at Minos Korva in one hour.
Aye, sir.
Set course 350 mark 215
and engage at warp 8.5.
( mumbling ):
♪ Sur le pont... d'avignon...
l'on y... l'on y danse... ♪
Wake up.
Where were you?
At home.
Sunday dinner.
We would all
sing afterwards.
What a charming picture.
The Picard family...
voices raised in song.
Is that what's keeping you
from breaking?
Memories of home
and hearth?
Images of happier times?
I must
congratulate you.
You're remarkably
strong-willed.
I see no point
in holding you further.
You may go.
Someone will give you
clean clothing
before we return you
to your ship.
We will get what we need
from the human female.
What female are
you referring to?
The human who was part
of your abortive
assault team, of course--
Dr. Beverly Crusher.
What have you
done to her?
Not a thing.
She's quite safe.
I wanted to finish
my interviews with you
before I interrogated her.
I had hoped
it might not be necessary.
Lieutenant Worf?
He left us few options.
We had to kill him.
I'm more optimistic
about getting what we need
from the woman.
Dr. Crusher has no knowledge
of any Starfleet operations.
She's a medical officer.
You might be right, I'll have
to determine that for myself.
Are you choosing
to stay with me?
Excellent.
I can't tell you
how pleased that makes me.
Starfleet now believes
the Cardassians
are preparing to
invade Minos Korva.
I'm convinced that
their invasion fleet
is hiding in
the McAllister Nebula.
I intend to hit it
before they leave it.
Captain,
what if you're wrong?
What if the Cardassians
are in that nebula
to conduct
scientific research?
You'd have to have
some pretty good evidence
to convince me of that.
You're still gambling
hundreds of lives.
This discussion is moot.
The plan has been approved
and we are going ahead.
Mr. Data,
by your calculations,
how long could the Cardassian
ships stay in the nebula?
In 17 hours,
their hull degradation
will reach dangerous levels.
They will have to
leave before that.
All right.
Worf, prepare a series
of 500 antimatter mines
with magnetic
targeting capabilities.
WORF: Aye, sir.
Geordi, we're going
to need a shuttle
specially outfitted to operate
in the nebula by 1400 hours.
Beverly, you'll need to...
Have Sick Bay ready
for the casualties
you're about to send me.
That's right.
Dismissed.
Ah, you're awake.
Have something to eat.
I insist.
Boiled taspar egg.
It's a delicacy
I'm happy to share with you.
( chuckling )
Wonderful.
I like you, human.
Most people become ill
at the sight of
live taspar.
I remember the first time
I ate a live taspar.
I was six years old
and living on the streets
of Lakat.
There was a band of children--
four, five, six years old
some even smaller--
desperately
trying to survive.
We were thin,
scrawny little animals,
constantly hungry,
always cold.
We slept together
in doorways
like packs of wild
gettles for warmth.
Once, I found a nest.
Taspars had mated
and built a nest
in the eaves of
a burnt-out building
and I found
three eggs in it.
It was like
finding treasure.
I cracked one open
on the spot and ate it,
very much
as you just did.
I planned to save
the other two.
They would keep me alive
for another week.
Of course, an older boy
saw them and wanted them...
and he got them.
But he had to
break my arm to do it.
( weakly )
Must be rewarding to you to...
to repay others for
all those years of misery.
What do you mean?
Torture has never been
a reliable means
of extracting information.
It is ultimately self-defeating
as a means of control.
One wonders that
it's still practiced.
I fail to see where this
analysis is leading.
Whenever I...
look at you now,
I won't see a powerful
Cardassian warrior.
I will see
a six-year-old boy
who is powerless
to protect himself.
Be quiet!
In spite of all
you have done to me,
I find you a pitiable man.
Picard, stop it
or I will turn this on
and leave you in agony
all night.
You called me "Picard."
What are the Federation's
defense plans for Minos Korva?
There are four lights.
( gasping painfully )
There are five lights.
How many do you see now?
You are six years old,
weak and helpless.
You cannot hurt me!
How many?
♪ Sur le pont... ♪
♪ ...d'avignon... ♪
♪ ...on'y danse... ♪
How are we doing?
We're almost done, sir.
I've shielded
the engine nacelles
and the transporter system,
so they won't be affected
by the particle flux
from the nebula.
Good.
Been a while since
I flew one of these.
You're a pilot yourself,
aren't you, Geordi?
Yes, sir.
Began my career
as a shuttle pilot
on the Jovian run.
From Jupiter to
Saturn and back--
once a day,
every day.
Is that right?
I was on that run myself
for a while.
Then, you must have
done Titan's turn.
Oh, yeah.
You set a course
directly for Titan,
hold it till you're just
brushing the atmosphere
throw the helm hard over
and whip around the moon
at point seven "C."
And pray like hell
nobody saw you.
You know, this trip into the
nebula is going to need someone
who can do Titan's turn
in their sleep.
These mines need to be laid
within two kilometers
of the Cardassian ships,
but the particle flux
from the nebula
will blind every sensor, except
for this proximity detector.
You're going to need one heck
of a pilot to pull that off.
Is that you?
I could do it,
but, truthfully,
the man you want
is Commander Riker.
He's the best there is.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Am I disturbing you?
Not at all.
Musician.
Yes.
Classical?
Contemporary?
Jazz.
Ah.
Is there something I can
do for you, Captain?
Are you aware of
our plans to attack
the Cardassian
invasion fleet?
Yes, sir.
I understand you've been talking
to every shuttle pilot on board.
Let's drop the
ranks for a moment.
I don't like you.
I think you're
insubordinate,
arrogant, willful
and I don't think
you're a particularly
good first officer,
but you are also
the best pilot on the ship.
Well...
now that the ranks
are dropped, Captain,
I don't like you either.
You are arrogant
and closed-minded.
You need to control
everything and everyone.
You don't provide
an atmosphere of trust
and you don't inspire
these people to go out of
their way for you.
You've got everybody
wound up so tight
there's no joy
in anything.
I don't think you're
a particularly good captain.
I won't...
order you to fly this mission.
Then ask me.
Will you pilot
the shuttle, Commander?
Yes.
You're welcome.
We've lost
primary navigation.
Switching
to secondary systems.
Inertial dampers
compensating.
Sensors inoperative.
Right on schedule.
LA FORGE:
Proximity detector is working.
We should be able
to read their ships
at a distance
of 500 meters.
Don't make this too easy.
( chuckles )
( beeping )
Hang on.
Do I want to know
how close that was?
No.
Get ready to deploy
the mines.
Captain, the shuttle
is emerging from the nebula.
Enterprise to shuttle.
Were you successful,
Commander?
RIKER: Aye, sir,
the mines are laid.
Very well.
Red alert.
Stand by to detonate
the mines on my command.
Standing by.
Open a channel
to the Reklar.
This is Cardassian territory,
Captain.
Your presence here is another
deliberate provocation...
I'm not going to argue
with you, Gul Lemec.
Every one of your ships
has a mine on its belly,
my finger's on the button and
you're in a very bad position.
You can't intimidate us.
Mr. Worf,
set off alpha-four-two.
Aye, sir.
JELLICO:
That was just a baby...
the big boys are
sitting on your hull
just waiting for me
to say the word.
What are your terms?
Your ships will leave
the nebula one by one.
Each ship will eject
its primary phaser coil
before setting course
for the nearest Cardassian base.
But that will leave us
defenseless.
Mr. Worf,
prepare to detonate...
I will agree to your terms.
Excellent.
Oh, and one more thing.
I understand you're holding
a Starfleet officer
named Jean-Luc Picard.
I expect him returned...
immediately.
That won't help.
I have many more.
Still, it felt good.
Enjoy your good feelings
while you can.
There may not be
many more of them.
I've just received word.
There's been a battle.
The Enterprise
is burning in space.
The invasion of Minos Korva
has been successful.
I don't believe you.
There's no need for any further
information from you.
Our troops were successful
in spite of your refusal
to help me.
You might have saved yourself
a great deal of torment
by yielding
at the beginning.
I want... to see a...
neutral representative.
There is no such person.
The word will be that
you perished with your crew.
No one will ever know
that you are here with us
as you will be
for a long, long time.
You do, however,
have a choice.
You can live out your life
in misery, held here,
subject to my whims...
or you can live in comfort
with good food
and warm clothing...
women as you
desire them...
allowed to pursue your studies
of philosophy and history.
I would enjoy
debating with you.
You have a keen mind.
It's up to you.
A life of ease, of reflection,
and intellectual challenge...
or this.
What must I do?
Nothing, really.
Tell me...
how many lights you see.
How many?
How many lights?
This is your last chance.
The guards are coming.
Don't be a stubborn fool.
How many?
You told me
he would be ready to go.
We had some
unfinished business.
Get him cleaned up.
A ship is waiting to take him
back to the Enterprise.
Captain Picard,
if you'll go with the guards,
they'll take care of you.
There... are...
four lights!
Captain on the Bridge.
Welcome home,
Jean-Luc.
Thank you.
Just the way you left it.
Maybe a little better.
Computer, transfer
all command codes
to Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
Voice authorization:
Jellico-alpha-three-one.
COMPUTER:
Transfer complete.
USS Enterprise
now under command
of Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
I relieve you, sir.
I stand relieved.
It's been an honor
serving with you.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Aye, sir.
I, uh...
I don't know
where to begin.
It was, uh...
I read your report.
What I didn't put
in the report
was that, at the end,
he gave me a choice
between a life of comfort...
or more torture.
All I had to do
was to say that
I could see five lights
when, in fact,
there were only four.
You didn't say it.
No. No...
but I was going to.
I would have told
him anything.
Anything at all.
But more than that...
I believed that
I could see...
five lights.