It was then
I began to suspect
that your brother did not die
by his own hand.
That he was, in fact...
murdered.
Murdered?
Good Lord.
But, Holmes, the vial of poison
found in his hand.
That was the first clue,
Watson.
The vial contained strychnine,
which, as you well know,
induces violent
muscular spasms.
It is difficult
to imagine
that someone in the throes
of so gruesome a death
could have held onto
so delicate a container
without shattering it.
You don't mean...
Exactly!
The vial was placed in his hand
after he died.
Then what was
the cause of death?
The cigar,
of course.
( coughing ):
Cigar?
Upon closer
investigation
of the room in which
your brother was found,
I discovered a fresh burn mark
on the carpet.
Further analysis
of the ash revealed
that the cigar was laced
with strychnine.
This is
utter nonsense.
What about
the suicide note?
It was written in
my dear brother's own hand.
With practice,
handwriting
can be forged.
It takes
a trained eye
to notice
certain discrepancies.
For example,
whether someone is right...
or left-handed.
Your brother
was right-handed.
The alleged suicide note
was written
by a left-handed
individual
such as yourself.
Uh, Data,
it's in his right hand.
( chuckling )
Curious.
There seems to be a problem
with the holodeck's
spatial orientation systems.
London's
greatest detective, huh?
Freeze program.
La Forge to Barclay.
BARCLAY: Barclay here.
Reg, something went wrong with
the holodeck program again.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll look into it right away.
Thanks, Reg.
We should get back
to engineering, Data.
Computer, end program
and save.
Whoa.
Whoa, Reg.
I'm sorry,
Commander.
I'm just on my way
to the holodeck.
Sherlock Holmes Program 3A
has demonstrated
some very curious
anomalies.
There must have
been a glitch in
the matrix diodes
but I'll track it down, don't
worry.
Thanks, Reg.
See you later.
Computer, run a diagnostic
on all Sherlock Holmes files.
Display any anomalous
programming sequences.
COMPUTER:
Diagnostic complete.
All files conform
to specified parameters
except those contained
in protected memory.
Protected memory?
All right,
display those sequences.
Computer, unlock this sequence
and run the program.
Who are you?
Professor
James Moriarty.
Moriarty,
oh.
That's Sherlock Holmes'
archenemy.
Are you left or right-handed?
Left-handed.
Would you mind very much
telling me...
No problem there.
Where is
Captain Picard?
Is he still captain
of this vessel?
How would...?
How do you know
the captain?
You don't know anything
about what happened, do you?
I have been stored in memory
for God knows how long
and no one has given me
a second thought.
You know!
You know
what you are!
A holodeck
character?
A fictional man?
Yes, yes, I know all about
your marvelous inventions.
I was created
as a plaything
so that your
Commander Data
could masquerade
as Sherlock Holmes
but they made me
too well
and I became more
than a character in a story.
I became
self-aware.
I am alive.
That's not possible.
But here I am.
Tell me, has a way
been found to allow me
to leave the confines
of this holodeck world?
Leave the holodeck?
No, of course not.
You can only
exist in here.
Damn you, Picard.
He promised me
something would be done.
I should have realized
he would have said anything
to get me to release
my hostage.
Hostage?
How long have I been
locked away?
Uh, well,
it looks...
looks like about,
uh... four years.
It seemed longer.
What are you
talking about?
You can't possibly
have been aware
of the passage
of time.
But I was.
Brief terrifying periods
of consciousness
disembodied
without substance.
I don't see how that
could be possible.
Maybe there was
a fragmentation
of the protected
memory circuits.
Call it
what you will.
All I know is that
despite Picard's promise,
he's done nothing.
Just left me
to go quietly mad.
He would not have
forgotten his promise.
The captain
would not do that.
I'd like to talk to him.
Well, I-I can ask...
Ask him to meet me
in the sitting room
at Baker Street.
That would be
far more appropriate.
I'll have to store you
in memory again
until I get an answer.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46424.1.
The Enterprise has arrived
at the Detrian System
to observe
a unique celestial event--
the collision of two planets.
Since both planets
are gas giants
neither possesses
a solid surface.
Their atmospheres, however,
will come into contact
in approximately
17 hours, nine minutes.
If their collision
causes
a self-sustaining
fusion reaction,
this is what
we are likely to see--
the birth
of a new star.
The Enterprise
will hold position
until the gravitational
instability subsides
and we can get in
for a closer look.
Now I want triple redundancy
on all of the sensor arrays.
We'll probably never
get another chance
to see something like this.
I don't want
to miss anything, okay?
Commander, you'll never
believe what happened
while I was working on your
program in the holodeck.
Professor Moriarty appeared
out of nowhere.
What?
And he wants to talk
to the captain.
Computer, begin
Sherlock Holmes Program 3A
and place us in the drawing room
at 221-B Baker Street.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
Computer, access
protected memory
and run
Moriarty program.
Professor.
It's good
to see you again.
If you'd missed
my company,
I should think you'd have
summoned me before now.
I assure you,
we have not forgotten you.
We spent time investigating
how you became
self-aware.
Frankly, it still
remains a mystery.
It is also
irrelevant.
What concerns me is finding
a way to leave the holodeck.
We have been wrestling
with that problem, too
unfortunately,
without any success.
But we have turned
our findings over
to Starfleet's most experienced
theoretical scientists.
And what did your finest
minds come up with?
Unfortunately, they have not
arrived at a solution either.
I see.
Professor,
I am concerned
to learn that you experienced
the passage of time
while you were stored
in the computer
memory.
I can assure you
we had no idea
that would be the case.
Enough of this.
I no longer believe
anything you say.
Professor, I understand
your frustration.
Do you really?
When this is over,
you will walk out of this room
to the real world
and your own concerns
and leave me here
trapped in a world
I know to be nothing
but illusion.
I cannot bear that.
I must leave.
That is not possible.
You cannot exist
outside this room.
Are you certain
of that?
Computer, exit.
Although objects appear
solid on the holodeck
in the real world,
they have no substance.
An object
has no life.
I do.
Professor, you are
a computer simulation.
I have
consciousness.
Conscious beings
have will.
The mind endows them
with powers
that are not
necessarily understood
even by you.
If my will
is strong enough
perhaps I can exist
outside this room.
Perhaps I can walk
into your world right now.
Professor, I ask you
to believe me.
If you step out of that door,
you will cease to exist.
If I am nothing more
than a computer simulation
then very little
will have been lost
but if I am right...
Mind over matter.
Cogito ergo sum.
I think,
therefore I am.
Data to security.
Send two officers
to holodeck three.
How is this
possible?
BARCLAY:
It isn't.
This contradicts everything we
know about holodeck physics.
Then perhaps you don't know
as much as you thought.
Professor, will
you come with me?
I'd like our doctor
to examine you.
Certainly, sir.
Policemen--
I'd recognize them
in any century.
As far as I can
tell, he's real.
He's human.
What else would I be,
dear lady?
His DNA is a little unusual,
but all the major systems
are there and
functioning normally.
As far as I can tell,
there's no evidence
that his molecules
are losing any cohesion.
They seem to be as immutable
as ordinary matter.
Well, Professor, my crew
will continue to investigate
but, for now, it would seem that
you have accomplished a miracle.
The question is,
now that you're here,
what do we do with you?
I ask only that I be allowed
to explore this new world.
Your vessel, for instance--
what sea
does she sail?
Might we go
above deck?
Weather permitting,
of course.
Professor, I think
there are some things
of which you
should be made aware.
( quiet conversation
and laughter )
My God.
We're adrift
in the heavens.
No, not adrift.
The Enterprise
is a starship
capable of traveling
through space.
Extraordinary.
Are we far
from Earth?
What is the range
of this ship?
What means of locomotion
does it use?
There's so much
for me to learn.
I hardly know where
to start.
I can give you books
that will help.
Good, good.
I want to start
making plans.
Determine what I'm going
to do with my life.
I hope you will plan on
remaining on board for a while.
There is still much
that we need to understand
about what has
happened to you.
Does it really matter?
The point is I'm here
and I'm eager
to get on with life.
Professor,
I feel it necessary
to point out
that criminal behavior
is as unacceptable
in the 24th century
as it was in the 19th
and very much harder
to get away with.
Don't worry,
Captain.
My past is nothing
but a fiction--
the scribblings of an Englishman
dead now for four centuries.
I hope to leave his books
on the shelf, as it were.
If that is so,
then there are opportunities
awaiting you
that are beyond anything
you have ever imagined.
Your century
may welcome me, but...
What is the matter?
In considering
all these vast possibilities
I suddenly feel
very much alone.
I am a man out
of time, Captain,
and that isolates me.
You have been more gracious
than I ever could have imagined.
I wonder...
May I impose upon
your generosity once again?
There is a woman--
the Countess Regina
Barthalomew.
She was created
as a holodeck character
for one of
Commander Data's programs.
She was designed to be
the love of my life.
Could she also
be brought off
the holodeck?
Professor, I ask you
to believe me when I say
that we do not know
how or why
you are able to exist
off the holodeck.
I do.
I do believe you.
According to the laws
of physics, this is impossible.
We would have no idea
how to do it again.
As I understand it,
I was endowed with consciousness
four years ago
when someone said
to the computer
"Create an opponent with
the capacity to outthink Data"
or words to that effect.
Could we not make
a similar request
on behalf of the countess?
Even if I had reason to believe
that it would be successful
I don't think
that I could sanction it.
Please understand,
Professor,
that you are, in essence,
a new life-form--
one that we didn't
intend to create
and that we don't
fully understand.
Now, the moral and ethical
implications
of deliberately creating
another one like you
are overwhelming.
Is it morally
and ethically acceptable
to deny the woman I love
so that you can put
your conscience at ease?
Are you saying that
you will simply dictate
how I am to live my life?
I assure you, we will do
everything possible
to make you comfortable.
So long as
I accept the terms
under which you dole out
those comforts.
Captain...
I am a powerless man.
You hold my future,
my happiness
my very life
in your hands.
Please...
consider my request.
I understand
his frustration.
We created him and we created
her to be the woman he loves.
Surely we have some
responsibility to them.
It's very romantic
but until we know just what it
was that walked off the holodeck
I don't think we should be
trying it again.
Even if we decided to do it
there's no guarantee
that we'd be able to.
DATA:
There is also no way
of knowing
if the professor's ability
to exist off the holodeck
is permanent.
It may be unwise to consider
creating a second individual
while this uncertainty
exists.
Agreed.
We don't have enough information
about this phenomenon
to act responsibly.
I think we'll hold off on
Professor Moriarty's
request for now
but continue with
your investigation.
In the meantime,
I have to deal
with Professor Moriarty.
I feel we must postpone
action until we learn more.
Yes, you know
all about that.
I stayed in the dungeon
of your computer for years
waiting for you
to learn more.
It wasn't until I took matters
into my own hands
that
something got done.
Professor, I wonder why you
are in so much of a hurry?
Is this woman
involved with you
in some illegal
venture?
Your computer
designed her
to be a person
of impeccable integrity.
She would never
commit a crime.
You must love her
very much.
The program fashioned her
for me to love.
But I must admit,
I would have done so anyway.
She is remarkable.
My life has not been the same
since I met her.
I don't simply love her,
Captain.
I adore her.
Then her safety must be
very important to you.
Give us time to determine
what is going on here.
That way we can minimize
the risks in
bringing her to you.
You wouldn't want
to lose her
because we acted
too quickly.
RIKER: Riker to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
Could you join us
on the bridge?
On my way.
RIKER:
There they are, Captain.
How long before they begin
to coalesce?
Within the next
five hours, sir.
PICARD:
Mr. Worf,
launch four Class-A probes
towards the planet.
Aye, sir.
( loud beeping )
Mr. Worf?
I-I don't understand.
The controls are not
responding.
Command functions
are being rerouted, sir.
For what reason?
Unknown, sir.
Computer,
route all command functions
to the bridge.
COMPUTER: Command functions
are off-line.
Reinitialize them
on my authorization.
COMPUTER: Authorization denied.
Explain.
Picard command codes
are no longer valid.
What's happening?
Who's transferred
the voice authorization?
I have.
I'm afraid
I had no choice
but to take control
of your vessel.
If you harm me, sir,
I will not be able to relinquish
voice control
of your vessel.
Professor,
this situation
is more serious
than you realize.
In less than five hours,
those two planets will collide
and a new star
will form.
Unless we move
to a safe distance
this vessel will
be destroyed.
I'm just
a fictional character.
I haven't much
to lose.
But surely, you wish to live
like the rest of us.
Not alone.
Not without the countess.
We've discussed
that.
We are studying means
of bringing her safely
off the holodeck,
but five hours
is not enough time.
I'm not so sure.
A deadline has
a wonderful way
of concentrating the mind.
Mr. Data,
will you investigate
the possibility
of complying
with Professor Moriarty's
request?
Aye, sir.
In the meantime,
we have a few things
to discuss.
Perhaps we should consider
the transporter system.
It uses many of
the same principles
as the holodeck.
Both, for example,
are capable
of converting
energy into matter.
Except the transporter
reconstitutes energy
in a permanent form.
Holodeck matter
doesn't have any cohesion
unless it's inside the grid.
I wonder
what would happen
if we tried to beam
a holodeck object off the grid?
Nothing
would happen.
A holodeck object
is just a simulation.
There's nothing there
to provide a pattern lock
for the transporter.
However,
if it were possible
to lock onto the object
it might rematerialize with
the same molecular cohesion
as conventional matter.
That's a big leap,
Data.
I just don't think
the transporter is going
to accept simulated matter.
Unless... unless we
could find a way
to compensate for
the phase variance.
If we could modify
the pattern enhancers
we just might do it.
Well, Professor Moriarty
has agreed not to interfere
with routine ship operations.
So long as he believes that
we are acting in good faith,
then I don't think
we're in immediate danger.
Any progress?
We were just talking
about using the transporter
to beam the countess
off the holodeck,
but I don't quite see
how it's going to work.
Well, keep at it.
I have to tell him that we
are making some progress.
Mr. La Forge?
Do you have any idea
how Moriarty
could have gained
control of the ship?
Somehow he managed
to override
the security lockouts
and rewrite them.
The man is brilliant
in any century.
I want you to find some way
to undo what he has done
so that we can regain
control of this ship.
Set the pattern enhancers
around whatever object
you wish to transport.
I will proceed
to the transporter room
and begin
modifications.
Computer, run
Sherlock Holmes program 3A.
COMPUTER: That program
is already in use.
Have you come
to see Mr. Holmes
or perhaps
Professor Moriarty?
Neither is in just now.
Um, uh, no, no, I'm not
here to see anyone.
I'm... just here
to deliver these.
Fine. Just, um...
put them anywhere.
Well, actually, I have
to put them right here.
How curious.
Why is that?
Well, it has to do with...
it is nothing you need
to worry about, Countess.
Are you suggesting that it's
beyond my comprehension?
It's really
very simple.
I need to enhance
the molecular pattern
of this chair
so that the transporter
can get a better
lock on the signal.
This has to do
with taking James and me
into the real world.
You, you...
you know about that?
I mean, you understand
about the real world?
James has explained it
to me.
It sounds like
a grand adventure.
There's nothing I love more
than voyaging in the unknown.
Have you ever been
to Africa, Mr.-- um...?
Uh, Barclay,
Lieutenant Reginald Barclay.
No. No, I haven't.
I have.
When I was 17, I went on safari
with my uncle.
My mother took
to her bed in terror
I'd be bitten
by a tsetse fly
but I had
a marvelous time.
I got to wear trousers
the whole time.
Oh, it was hard to go back
to a corset, I can tell you.
Yes, I'm sure it was.
After that, I never
stopped traveling.
Oh, I couldn't bear to be stuck
in one place for very long
so you see, I am so looking
forward to this new experience.
My...
Traveling the stars.
You know
about that?
Y-you, you know
where we are?
Countess, forgive me,
but you just don't sound
like a holodeck
character.
That's because she isn't.
James.
If you loved a woman
like this, Lieutenant,
would you be content to
let her remain a simulation?
You... you gave her
consciousness?
Yes, just as it
was given to me.
Well, I'm not so sure
that that's a good idea.
Nonsense. It was
the only thing to do.
Have you tried to take her
off the holodeck yet?
No. I'm unwilling to risk
the countess' safety.
I want to make sure
nothing will happen to her.
We may be closer to freedom
than you think, James.
These devices will enhance
our molecular patterns.
They'll help take us
into the real world.
Well, please,
proceed.
Well, we're going to try
to transport this chair
off the holodeck first.
We didn't want to try it
on the countess
until we were sure
it would work.
How thoughtful.
Isn't he thoughtful,
James?
Barclay to Commander Data.
Go ahead,
Lieutenant.
BARCLAY: I'm ready here.
Modifications
are complete.
DATA: Stand by.
Standing by.
Activating pattern enhancers.
Energizing.
I am having difficulty
establishing a pattern lock.
Boost the confinement beam,
please.
Pattern lock established.
Energizing.
Ooh!
Bravo!
Do you have the chair,
commander?
No.
It lost its cohesion
as soon as the transporter cycle
was complete.
( sighs )
Well, it was a...
a long shot to begin with.
DATA: Agreed,
however, we may be able
to learn something
from the attempt.
Computer,
display the transport logs
from the sequence
just completed.
Computer,
what is being displayed here?
Transport log 759.
That is the correct log,
however, no information
is being presented.
Well, th-that's
impossible.
DATA: It is almost as if
our attempt
to transport the chair
never occurred.
You wanted
to see me.
Ah, yes, Captain,
I think I found a way
to reinstate your
vocal authorizations.
Give it a try.
Computer,
route all command functions
to this location.
COMPUTER: Command functions
are off-line.
Reinitialize them
on my authorization.
Please input command codes.
Picard,
Epsilon-seven-nine-three.
COMPUTER:
Command codes verified.
That's it.
That should do it.
Wait a minute.
It didn't work.
The computer won't release
the command pathways.
Geordi.
Why did you do that, Data?
Captain...
I have determined
how Moriarty
was able to leave
the holodeck.
He never did.
Neither
did we.
None of this
is real.
It is
a simulation.
We are still
on the holodeck.
We're still on the holodeck?
How do you know that?
Through deduction,
sir.
Lieutenant Barclay
and I tried to transport
a simulated object
off the holodeck--
something that
has never been attempted.
Since the transporter itself
is a simulation
the computer
had no real data
from which to create
the transport logs.
Maybe it was just a malfunction
in the transporter.
Then I saw you working
the PADD with your left hand.
Commander La Forge
is right-handed, sir.
A similar malfunction
occurred
in the Sherlock Holmes
program I was running
before Moriarty
first appeared.
Mr. Data, if what
you say is true
then this is not
Geordi La Forge.
Are you certain?
Computer,
discontinue program.
Computer, exit.
Moriarty appears to have
programmed the holodeck
to accept
only his commands.
Picard to bridge.
RIKER: Riker here.
Number one,
what is my present location?
Engineering.
Is something wrong, sir?
No.
Thank you.
Picard out.
Our combadges must be
locked into the simulation.
If that had been
the real Commander Riker,
he would have given my location
as holodeck three.
Mr. La Forge
would you excuse us,
please?
Mr. Data,
who is real here?
You and I are real, sir,
as is Lieutenant Barclay.
We entered
the holodeck together
when we first went
to meet Moriarty.
And from that point
we have been existing
in a holodeck simulation
created by
Professor Moriarty.
I believe
that is the case, sir.
I have just given the
computer my command codes
thinking I would get
control of the ship.
You may have inadvertently given
Professor Moriarty the means
of gaining control
over the real Enterprise.
Since Professor Moriarty
never actually
left the holodeck
he may demand
that Commander Riker
help him to do so.
How long until the
planetary collision?
Less than
three hours.
As long as Moriarty
has control of the ship
we are vulnerable.
Somehow...
I have to find a way of
giving him what he wants.
Where is
Captain Picard?
And what have you done
with Lieutenant Barclay
and Commander Data?
They're safe...
for now.
Release control
of this ship.
I'm afraid
I can't do that.
What do you want?
I only want
what you have the luxury
of taking for granted--
Freedom.
I want to leave
this holodeck.
I think you know
that's impossible.
Your crewmates here
in my little ship in a bottle
seem a bit more optimistic.
Oh?
They attempted to use
your transporter device
to remove
a simulated object
from the holodeck.
If they tried it
they must have thought
they were onto something.
Their attempt
was futile
because their transporter
was a facsimile.
I expect more from you.
Just because our
transporter is real
doesn't mean
it's going to work.
I sense a distressing lack
of enthusiasm on your parts.
( alarm sounds )
Sir.
Warp core temperature
is rising.
Approaching critical levels.
I have nothing to lose,
Commander.
Mr. La Forge, start working
on the problem.
Aye, sir.
Core temperature dropping.
Computer,
resume program.
Hello.
Have we met?
Captain
Jean-Luc Picard.
Ah! James has told me
all about you.
Regina,
Countess Barthalomew.
Do sit down.
May I offer you
some tea, Captain?
Thank you, no.
I've come here
to prevail
on your intelligence
and your insight.
But not, apparently,
my humility.
Credit where
credit is due, madam.
I can see you are a woman
not only of breeding
but of wit
and sagacity.
And you, sir, are a man
of charm... and guile.
You remind me
of Viscount Oglethorpe.
He was a man
who could bewitch
any woman
who breathed.
And do you suspect that
that is my intent?
I cannot be certain
of your intent
but I am certain
you're the kind of man
who usually gets
exactly what he wants.
What does a woman like you
see in a man like Moriarty?
He is an exciting man,
Captain.
He's brilliant...
incisive...
He's ruthless.
He has an almost
irresistible appeal.
He's also
an arch criminal.
Only because he was
written like that.
I see him
entirely differently.
Captain, he is not
a villain.
So it's your desire to leave
the holodeck to be with him.
More than anything.
Can you help us?
Yes, I can.
We have learned
that if we uncouple
the transporter's
Heisenberg compensators
and allow them
to rescramble randomly
then we can beam
a holodeck object--
or a person--
off the grid,
with all of the cohesion
of conventional matter.
Oh!
Oh, that's
splendid.
I must tell James.
No, please.
Wait.
I have brought you
this information
because I think you are
someone who will listen
to a reasonable
proposition.
Someone whose mind
is open to compromise.
Yes?
My ship is in danger.
It is imperative
that I regain
navigational control.
I want you to persuade
Professor Moriarty
to return
the voice command to me
or I will not modify
the transporter.
I see.
Now, once I have
regained voice command
I will transport you
from the holodeck.
Forgive me, Captain,
but that does sound more like
a threat than a compromise.
Countess,
you must understand
that I am responsible
for more than 1,000 lives.
I will do what I can.
LA FORGE:
The gravity well is beginning
to intensify.
Are we far enough away
to keep from being pulled in?
( sighs )
It's too soon to tell.
Riker to
Lieutenant Worf.
WORF: Worf here, sir.
How are you doing?
There are force fields blocking
our access to the holodeck.
It will take time
to disable them.
RIKER: Keep trying.
Aye, sir.
Think, my dear.
You're certain he said
they had to uncouple the
Heisenberg compensators?
Yes, James.
I'm quite certain,
but he won't do it
unless you return control
of the ship to him.
I have them running
around like rats in a maze.
What harm
would there be
in accepting
his proposition?
My dear, you are
as brilliant
as you are beautiful.
Nonetheless,
there are things
you do not understand.
Now, please, you must
let me handle this.
Computer, arch.
Moriarty to Commander Riker.
Riker here.
Commander Riker,
a pleasure as always.
I don't have time for games,
Moriarty.
This ship is falling
into a gravity well.
It will be destroyed
within 25 minutes--
holodeck and all.
Then I'm sure
you'll be motivated
to listen to me
very, very carefully.
I want to talk to you
about uncoupling
the Heisenberg compensators.
James, when we leave here,
where exactly are we going?
Everywhere, my darling.
There are more worlds
in the heavens
than there are grains
of sand on a shoreline.
Oh, I wish I could
take my books.
I will be so
lost without them.
I'll get you more.
Don't worry.
I promise you, you'll
want for nothing.
Riker to Moriarty.
It's time.
Yes, Commander.
We're ready.
As are we.
Step into the transport area.
We're ready here.
Activating pattern enhancers.
Energizing.
Welcome aboard.
( laughing )
May I present Regina,
the Countess Barthalomew.
Countess.
Commander.
You'll forgive me if
I skip the formalities
considering
the circumstances.
Ah, yes,
I expect you want me
to relinquish my hold
on your vessel.
Please.
I'm afraid that won't
be possible just yet.
We had an agreement.
And I intend
to honor it.
I have no desire to see
your vessel destroyed.
Just give me one
of your... shuttlecraft
and allow us
to leave in peace.
We don't have
time for this.
You release those command codes
and we'll talk.
I will not
release your vessel
until I am looking at it
through a shuttlecraft window.
Everything
has been programmed
to operate
on voice command.
You just tell the computer
where you want to go.
Excellent.
I suggest you head
for Meles II.
It's the nearest
inhabited planet.
The people are friendly.
Where you go from there
is your business.
Please tell your captain
I'm sorry I couldn't
say good-bye.
I do wish I could
see his face
when he realizes where he's been
the last several hours.
Every second we waste puts us
in that much more danger.
Don't worry,
Commander.
You'll soon have
control of your ship.
Good-bye, Commander.
Thank you for everything.
Computer,
prepare to depart.
Open shuttle bay doors.
( warning klaxon sounds )
This is so
beautiful.
Indeed, my dear.
It is a wondrous sight--
the first of many we
are sure to encounter
in our travels.
Computer,
interface with
the central computer
on the Enterprise.
COMPUTER: Interface complete.
Release command
function lockouts.
Authorization: Moriarty,
alpha-two-four-one-five-nine.
James?
Yes, my love?
Can we go back
to Earth someday?
Of course, my dear.
Of course.
Computer, store program
Picard delta one
in active memory
and discontinue simulation.
COMPUTER:
Program stored.
Well, it worked.
They believed they were
off the holodeck.
Did Moriarty release
the voice commands, Captain?
Let's find out.
Computer, discontinue
holodeck simulation
created by
Professor Moriarty.
Well, so far,
so good.
This should be the holodeck
on the real Enterprise.
Picard to bridge.
RIKER:
Captain, are you all right?
Yes, we are, Number One.
What is your status?
Our systems came
back on line
a few minutes ago.
And the planetary collision?
We're pulling back
to a safe distance.
We'll join you shortly.
Captain.
Mr. Worf,
everything is all right.
How did you do it, sir?
We managed to program the
holodeck inside the holodeck
and used the same ruse
that Moriarty used on us.
DATA:
When he was attempting
to contact the real bridge
he was, in fact, speaking
to a simulation.
You mean, he never knew he
hadn't left the holodeck?
In fact, the program
is continuing to run
even now,
inside that cube.
A miniature holodeck?
In a way,
Doctor.
However, there is
no physicality.
The program is continuous,
but only within
the computer circuitry.
As far as Moriarty
and the countess know,
they're halfway
to Meles II by now.
This enhancement module
contains enough active memory
to provide them
with experiences
for a lifetime.
PICARD:
They will live their lives
and never know
any difference.
In a sense, you did give
Moriarty what he wanted.
In a sense, but who knows?
Our reality may be
very much like theirs
and all this might just be
an elaborate simulation
running inside a little device
sitting on someone's table.
Well, we have
a newborn star to study.
Mr. Barclay,
you will keep
that safe.
Aye, sir.
Computer, end program.