Captain's Log,
Stardate 46461.3.
We have arrived at
a communication relay station
near the Klingon border
where we are scheduled
to deliver supplies.
However, the station has not
responded to repeated hails.
( staticky indistinct voices )
CRUSHER:
What's that noise?
They must have left their
audio monitoring system on.
We're hearing a few thousand
subspace messages.
I'll try and shut it off.
Got it.
( thumping )
Geordi, what's that?
I don't know.
Sounds like a loose panel
or something.
I think it's coming from
this service duct over here.
Here's your loose panel.
( barks )
Hey, pooch.
Hey, pooch,
come on out of there.
Come on.
Hey, pooch, what are
you doing in there?
Commander,
the shuttlecraft is gone.
There is no one on board.
CRUSHER:
Commander.
What is it?
CRUSHER:
Cellular residue.
I believe these
are the remains
of one of
our lieutenants.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
All the blood traces
I found
match those of
Lieutenant Aquiel Uhnari.
I'll assume
those are her remains
but I need to take
the deckplate
back to sick bay
just to be sure.
It would take a powerful
weapon to do that.
I'll have a better idea
once I've analyzed
the deckplate.
If that is Uhnari,
where's Rocha?
The station's
shuttle's gone.
Maybe he took it.
Before Uhnari died
or after?
We're ready, Commander.
You have any luck
downloading the station logs?
Not yet. I can't get past
these security lockouts
and I think I know why.
All encrypted subspace messages
are sent through this channel.
Take a look at this
signal notation.
RIKER:
It's out of sequence.
Looks like somebody
trying to bypass
the access protocols
and break into
the coded messages.
It caused the security
lockouts to freeze right up.
Are there
any messages missing?
Well, I won't know until
I get into the files.
Looks like
you made a friend.
Yep.
I've got to go back
to the ship.
Let me know as soon
as you have something.
I'm going to try
accessing the logs
from another console.
What's going on here?
( sighs ):
Well, we can start with
repolarizing the interface.
( dog barks )
What is it, pup?
What's the matter?
Something over here?
This doesn't look
like it belongs to you.
Ah...
this is what you want, huh?
( barks )
There you go.
Computer, run station logs
in sequence.
WOMAN:
Station log, Stardate 46458.3.
Today we configured
the relay controller grid.
It was the last primary system
we had to overhaul.
We are scheduled to recalibrate
and align the antennae systems
in the next three days.
Computer,
access visual output.
( static )
...sent in my third request
for a message delay buffer.
Until it arrives,
Lieutenant Rocha and I
have rigged a memory module
to compensate.
It better work, or about
a half million subspace messages
are going to end up drifting
through space.
Computer, open
Uhnari correspondence file.
( static )
Computer,
access correspondence files,
Lieutenant Aquiel Uhnari.
( static )
( beeping )
WOMAN:
Hello, Shiana.
Sorry I haven't talked
to you in a while
but I've been dealing with
the new lieutenant, Rocha.
So far he's been rude,
arrogant and condescending
and he's only been here
two days.
This might be a long year.
( static )
Come on, Lieutenant,
stick with me.
I had the dream again.
Mother's calling out
my name.
She's somewhere in the house.
I get to the top
of the hill all right
but then the house
is slanted.
I'm still walking uphill.
I can't find her.
Doors everywhere,
and they all look the same.
( static )
The cellular residue
is completely fused
to the metal
of the deckplate.
We're trying to micro-
vaporize the metal
in order to get
a clear DNA sample.
Do you have any idea
what killed her?
Well, this is
just a guess
but from the molecular
deposition of the plating
I'd say it was caused
by a high-level
phaser blast.
Could it have been
a Klingon disrupter?
Possibly.
Geordi's found evidence
that the encrypted messages
have been
tampered with
and we are close
to Klingon space.
There hasn't been
a Klingon raid
against the Federation
for more than seven years.
I don't want to risk
a diplomatic incident
until I have more evidence.
And there's still
the question
of what happened
to Lieutenant Rocha.
Get Rocha's personnel file
from Starfleet Command
and ask Starbase 212
if they will help us
to find the shuttle.
Aye, sir.
Keep me apprised, doctor.
All right,
let's try this again.
Come on, this
should be working.
The phase inducers
are aligned.
Come on, Lieutenant,
I know you're in here somewhere.
Computer, run me
a subsystems diagnostic
with a frequency range
of ten to 100 megahertz.
COMPUTER:
Diagnostic cycle
will be complete in 20 seconds.
Iced coffee.
( barks )
What is it, girl?
Hello, Shiana.
There you go.
By the time you get this,
the Batarael will be over.
This is the first time
I haven't been there.
I've been wondering.
Who's singing the Horath
in my place?
♪ Jomiael hahnalia ♪
♪ Ma marou nitalia ♪
♪ Rumael ♪
♪ Tavariel ♪
♪ Fatra di va ♪
♪ Jomiael... ♪
I had that dream again--
the one where Mother
is screaming.
I climb the hill to our house
but I, I can't get to her.
Shiana, this time I ran away.
I was so scared
I ran back down the hill.
I, I think I know why I've been
having the dreams about danger.
It's because of what's been
happening with that Klingon.
He's getting more aggressive
all the time.
Not just the usual threat...
( log rewinding )
It's because of what's been
happening with that Klingon.
He's getting more aggressive
all the time.
Not just the usual threat.
Morag actually locked
his disruptors
to the station this time.
I don't think
there'll be any trouble.
It just... brings up
those feelings of... panic,
of wanting to run, wanting
to get away from danger.
Shiana, I couldn't say this
to anyone but you
but the panic...
is the same thing I used to feel
whenever Father got angry,
when I knew
he was going to punish me.
Only now,
I'm out here in space...
and there's
nowhere to run.
There are three references
to a Commander Morag,
a Klingon officer who patrols
this section of the border.
Apparently, he would pass
by the station
every few days
and harass them.
Perhaps this Morag was
the one who was interested
in obtaining
the encrypted messages.
Could be.
She didn't say.
But I do have several
more days of logs to watch.
I'm hoping to learn more.
Very well.
In the meantime,
I'll speak with
the Klingon governor
about Commander Morag.
Are you saying we
attacked your outpost?
I'm merely saying
that I'm following up
on evidence that my officers
discovered on board.
Evidence.
So you are making
an accusation.
The Klingon empire will not
stand for these kinds of lies.
Governor Torak,
I apologize.
I can see that you
honestly didn't know
what happened
aboard the station.
I will just have to take
this matter up with Gowron.
I'm really sorry
that we bothered you.
Gowron won't bother with
such a minor incident.
Well, ordinarily
he wouldn't,
but, of course, I was
his arbiter of succession.
I'm sure that
he will be happy
to come here and
investigate this matter.
You needn't worry about it
any longer.
Gowron will come here?
Oh, yes.
So, once again, thank
you for your help.
Oh, I will be sure
to mention your name
to Gowron
when I speak to him.
I will investigate
this further, Picard.
You need not
bother Gowron
with this matter.
That's very kind.
Qapla'!
Computer,
access the personal logs
of Aquiel Uhnari.
COMPUTER:
Logs accessed.
Begin playback.
Shiana, you always said
I'd look great in a wig
so... here it is.
What do you think?
Hmm?
Definitely not you.
Okay, maybe I'm getting
a little crazy.
You would, too,
if you were stuck
on a relay station
in the middle of nowhere
with no one for company
except an egomaniac
like Keith Rocha.
I took
a big risk today.
I countermanded
an order he gave.
I agreed to handle
the com traffic
for relay station 194
while they shut down
for maintenance.
Rocha said we couldn't handle
the additional signal load
but I think he's wrong.
When he finds out,
he'll be furious.
It's days like this
I wish I was home.
You know what I miss most?
Muskan seed punch.
Real muskan seed punch.
You can get it
from the replicator
but it's not the same.
I'd give anything
for some of the punch
Mother used to make
with chunks of the seed
still in it.
( thumping )
Keith, is that you?
Keith?
( static )
Commander.
There are DNA traces
here-- Klingon.
So Klingons did board
this station.
Yes, but I only found DNA
from one Klingon so far.
I will continue
to scan.
( chuckling )
How could she read
this stuff?
How's it going?
I've managed to access all
of Lieutenant Uhnari's logs.
I'm still looking
for Lieutenant Rocha's.
Whatever happened
to the encrypted messages
had a cascade effect
on the whole storage system.
I can't find his files
anywhere,
but I'm running a
level-3 diagnostic now.
Well, maybe Rocha didn't
make the official logs.
Uhnari could have been
responsible for them.
I don't think so.
Aquiel was
the junior officer here.
Aquiel?
Lieutenant Uhnari.
I've been up all night
watching her personal logs.
I guess I'm starting
to feel like I know her.
What was she like?
Well, she was Haliian.
She had one sister
named Shiana.
She drank
muskan seed punch.
She... had
a quirky sense of humor.
She liked to sing.
She... had questionable
taste in literature.
PICARD:
Enterprise to Commander Riker.
Riker here.
The Klingon ship Qu'vat
has arrived with
Governor Torak.
Please report
to the observation lounge.
We're on our way.
Governor Torak, sir.
Governor, welcome aboard.
Do not bore me
with your human pleasantries.
I told you
we did not kill the woman.
Now I will prove it to you.
Ghos!
This is Lieutenant
Aquiel Uhnari.
We were running
a level-2 diagnostic
of the message buffer--
nothing special.
Rocha had been on edge
all morning,
but he'd been irritable
ever since he got there
so I didn't think
anything of it.
We were halfway
through the procedure
when suddenly he...
attacked me.
He grabbed me, threw me
against a bulkhead.
I yelled at him to stop,
but he wouldn't listen.
He took me by the throat.
I broke free and tried to get
to the weapons locker.
I'm not sure
what happened next
but somehow, I got aboard
the shuttle and left.
We found her
on our side of the border
heading toward
sector 2520.
She is lucky my patrol ship
did not destroy her vessel
on sight.
Lieutenant...
why didn't you
contact Starfleet?
Let them know
what had happened
on board the station?
I don't know, sir.
Maybe I passed out.
I'm not even sure how long
I was on the shuttle
before the Klingons
picked me up.
46 hours. You've been
gone 46 hours.
We presumed you were dead.
Your bloodstains were
found at the murder scene.
I must have cut my head
when he pushed me
against the bulkhead.
Then the remains
we found
must be those of
Lieutenant Rocha.
I can't confirm that.
Until we're able
to separate
the cellular residue
from the deckplate
I won't be able to do
a clear DNA scan.
You said you were trying
to get to the weapons locker.
Is there a possibility
that you did?
No, I... didn't.
You're sure?
I don't remember
exactly what happened to me
after I was attacked.
I'm sorry.
It's as if all my memories
were drained out of me.
Your log said
that a Commander Morag
had been harassing you.
Did you let him
or any other Klingon
onto the station?
Absolutely not.
If that is true, then Morag
or some other Klingon
must have boarded the
station after she left.
We found traces
of Klingon DNA
on the station.
You still try to blame us!
Have the courage to
admit your mistakes.
Or are you a lo'be vos?
At least I do not wear
the uniform of the petaQ!
Governor, we're
merely exploring
all the possibilities.
Lieutenant Uhnari's logs
reported that
Commander Morag
had been harassing
the station.
He was doing his job.
If he was only
doing his job
then I'm sure
you would not mind
if we spoke with him.
Very well.
In the interests
of diplomacy
I will allow you
to speak to Morag
but my patience
has limits!
Lieutenant, I know
a friend of yours
who's very eager
to see you.
Who?
Come with me.
( barks )
Maura! Come here, girl!
Come on, Maura!
Maura! That's
the name, huh?
Yes, it's from
Cold Moon Over Blackwater.
Have you read it?
I'm not much
for Gothic fiction.
Well, not many people
are, nowadays.
Oh, your shoe.
Uh, yeah. Maura got
a little restless.
Maura, shame on you.
That's not like you.
What a naughty dog.
It's all right.
Don't worry about it.
At least she's
chewing them up in pairs.
I'll arrange
quarters for you.
I'm sure you want
some time alone.
Well, actually, I've been
stuck on that station
for over nine months.
I wouldn't mind going
someplace with some activity.
I know just the place.
There you are, sir.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Ah!
Mmm! Oh.
Have you ever tried
muskan seed punch?
Uh... it nearly
made me sick.
You have
to be raised on it.
It's very nutritious.
The taste
grows on you.
Batar al nalia.
You speak Haliian?
We traveled around
quite a bit
while I was growing up.
I picked up a couple of
languages along the way.
Hmm.
We never traveled.
My family lived
in the same house
for five generations.
Mm-hmm.
The one on the hill.
How do you know
about that?
( sighs )
Well, to be honest, when
we thought you were dead
I needed to review your logs
and personal correspondence
for any possible clues
about what happened.
All of it?
Most of it, yeah.
You... you need
to understand
that we thought
you'd been murdered.
We needed information.
I'm sorry.
It's just that
I tell my sister
things I wouldn't
tell anyone else.
I guess I was feeling
a little... exposed.
I'd feel the same way.
Especially if I had
seen you in that wig.
( laughing )
It really wasn't you.
I'm curious.
Now that you've met me,
am I what you expected?
Hmm...
actually, I'm...
I'm not sure.
The woman I saw on those logs
is very complicated.
I think
there's more to you
than meets the eye,
Lieutenant.
In what way?
Well, your relationship with
Lieutenant Rocha, for example.
He was only there
for five days
and yet there was evidence
of plenty of friction.
And you seemed to delight
in doing things that...
you knew would upset him.
Why take on
extra com traffic
when you knew it was
going to make him angry?
Is this
a personal question
or part of a murder
investigation?
I don't know.
Maybe both.
Keith Rocha was obnoxious
from the minute
he reported to duty.
He treated me as though
I was beneath contempt.
I felt like
I had to battle him
to hold my own
but I didn't want
to see him dead.
Why do you think
he attacked you?
I don't know.
Rocha's file is spotless.
Two decorations for valor,
three outstanding evaluations
from his previous commanders.
It doesn't sound
like the same man
that Lieutenant Uhnari
described.
What did you find
out about Uhnari?
I checked into
her record, too.
Her last posting
was on Deriben V.
I spoke to her
commanding officer.
He said she was
argumentative,
quick to take offense.
He also told me
he transferred her
to that relay station
because she was
"hampering their efforts."
To be honest,
I'm having trouble
believing her story, sir.
Why?
I sent Worf to check
the weapons locker
on the relay station.
There's a phaser missing.
You think that she lied?
Lied, conveniently forgot--
I'm not sure.
I think it's something
we have to consider.
As of now we don't have
sufficient evidence,
one way or the other.
I want you
to examine her shuttle.
You might find
something there
that will shed some light on her
story.
Aye, sir.
How much longer do you think
the investigation will take?
Three, maybe four days.
It's tough to tell.
I know I'm a suspect
in the murder.
Let me ask you something.
You've watched my logs.
You know me better
than anyone here.
Do I seem like
the kind of person
who would murder someone?
No, you don't.
I don't think I realized
how much I needed to hear that.
Look, Aquiel, it's been
a rough couple of days.
I think
you need some sleep.
You called me complicated.
You're right.
I don't make
friends easily.
Oumriel.
Commander.
It is set to kill.
We found this type-2 phaser
in your shuttlecraft.
It was taken from
the weapons locker
on the station.
I told you I don't
remember what happened.
Maybe I did make it
to the weapons locker.
It was set
to level ten.
Standard procedure
requires that all phasers
are set on level one when
they're put in storage.
That means that somebody
deliberately changed
the setting.
And then there's the matter
of your conflict
with Lieutenant Rocha.
Rocha and I
had our disagreements
but that does not mean
I would kill him.
Have you been
able to remember
anything that happened
after he attacked you?
No.
Nothing.
I suppose, maybe
in self-defense, I...
Dr. Crusher tells me
that in order to inflict
the type of molecular damage
found in Rocha's remains,
it would take a sustained
phaser discharge
of at least
30 to 40 seconds.
That doesn't sound like
self-defense to me.
Now, wait a minute.
We haven't even
established
this phaser is
the murder weapon yet.
And even at level ten,
I don't see
how it could have
done the damage
the medical evidence
says it did.
A phase disrupter
like a Klingon weapon,
maybe...
Look, we're not here
to make accusations.
We're trying to find out
what happened.
Commander Morag is
due here in two hours.
Let's see
what he has to say.
Fine.
In the meantime
I'd like to go back
down to the station
and see if I can access
Rocha's personal logs again.
Good idea.
Geordi, wait a second.
Thank you, Mr. Worf.
Aye, sir.
This is off the record.
I'm saying this to you
as a friend,
not your superior officer.
I think it would be best
if you weren't
so personally involved
with Aquiel right now.
There's a lot about her
we don't know.
And there's a lot
about her that I do know
and if she's innocent
I want to help
her prove it.
I think you've let
your personal feelings
cloud your judgment.
I'm not the one
making judgments.
Got it.
Computer, display the personal
records of Lieutenant Rocha
from Stardates 46455
to 46460.
Computer, what happened
to the log entries
for Stardate 46459?
COMPUTER:
The logs have been deleted.
Who deleted them?
COMPUTER:
Unknown.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
The Qu'vat has arrived
with Commander Morag.
We are preparing
to question him
regarding his involvement
in the murder
of Lieutenant Rocha.
I killed no one!
We found your DNA on
the bulkheads and the console.
We know you were there.
Answer
their questions.
Yes...
yes, I was there.
My patrol route
takes me
near the station
every six days.
Three days ago,
I hailed them.
There was no response.
I was... concerned.
Concerned.
MORAG: Yes.
I went aboard to see
what had happened.
There was no one there,
so I left.
Is that all?
That's all.
Commander Morag,
we have discovered that
the encrypted message bank
on the station
has been tampered with.
Our analysis indicates that 27
priority Starfleet messages
are missing.
What of it?
Your DNA was also found
on the message
control module.
This is outrageous!
We will not tolerate
these ridiculous accusations.
TORAK:
This is a diplomatic
matter, Morag!
Do not make me
search your ship.
Yes...
I did take
the messages.
Did you kill
Lieutenant Rocha?
No, I killed no one.
There was no one there.
I took the codes,
but I killed no one.
Governor, we would like
Commander Morag
to remain on board
the Enterprise
until this investigation
is completed.
Take him.
This way.
Last night,
after I dropped you off
at your quarters
you established a subspace
link with this console.
You deleted some of Rocha's
personal files, didn't you?
Yes.
I did.
Why?
I found a letter
Rocha was planning to send
to Starfleet Command about me.
The letter said I had become
belligerent and insubordinate.
He was going to ask
for a formal hearing.
Geordi, I know
how this looks.
Yeah, it looks bad.
I find out that
you've erased a letter
that contained a possible
motivation for murder...
I didn't kill him!
Then explain this.
I was afraid that
if they found the letter
they'd blame me
for the murder.
I'm not a model officer.
I realize that.
Sometimes
I act on impulse
instead of
thinking things through.
Aquiel... this really
complicates things.
What are you doing?
Getting out of here.
Aquiel, running away
isn't going to prove
your innocence.
Facing the situation will.
I'm scared, Geordi.
Look, we'll get
through this.
I promise you, okay?
Then you believe me?
Yes, I do.
Medical officer's log,
supplemental.
I've isolated the cellular
residue from the deckplate,
but the DNA
has destabilized.
I'm attempting to reform it.
All right, initiate
the resonance frequency burst.
I'm beginning to get
a stable DNA scan.
This is odd.
The nucleotide sequences
are beginning to fluctuate.
The DNA is becoming motile.
Let's try another
frequency burst,
but increase
the resonance level
by 20%.
I haven't been this
close to someone
in a long time.
I don't want
to let go of it.
Neither do I, but...
we've got 600 logs
to go through.
All right.
But first there's
something I want
to share with you.
What?
A way that we can
become more intimate.
My people are
partially telepathic.
We use something
called the canar
to help focus
our thoughts.
We also use the canar
for a stronger emotional
link during love.
I was wondering
what that was for.
Do both of us
have to be telepathic
for it to work?
Let's find out.
Like this.
Think of me.
It's an exact
reproduction of my hand,
right down to
the DNA structure.
Doctor, you said
that this was formed
from the organic matter
taken from the deckplates.
When I infused
the matter
with a resonance
frequency burst
it activated its DNA.
Then it touched my hand
and it began to mimic
my cellular structure.
Doctor,
what exactly is this?
This is going to sound
very far-fetched,
but have you ever heard
of a coalescent organism?
No.
They're rare
microscopic life-forms
which need to absorb
other organisms
in order to survive.
Now, that in itself
isn't so unusual,
but coalescents
become the organisms
they've absorbed--
right down to
the cellular level.
Do you think this is what
happened with your hand?
There have been reports
that these organisms can
exist on a larger scale.
Certainly what
happened to my hand
seems to support
that theory.
RIKER:
So you think that Rocha
was killed by one
of these organisms?
It's possible that
something happened to him
before he reported for duty
on the relay station.
I do not understand.
I've checked
the records.
Before he was posted
to the relay station
Rocha served on an outpost
in the Triona system.
Now, that is
a remote sector.
Maybe he was absorbed
by a coalescent
during that mission.
So, what boarded the station
could have been
an organism that looked
and acted like
Lieutenant Rocha.
How often do they
have to change bodies?
The microscopic organisms
have a cycle of no more
than five to ten seconds.
We can only assume
that a larger,
more complex coalescent
would have a cycle
of days...
even weeks.
Doctor, if what
you're saying is true
then Rocha attacked
Lieutenant Uhnari
to find a new body.
Right.
That means Uhnari
is a coalescent.
There was one other person
on the station--
Morag.
It is possible
he was the one who was...
absorbed.
Computer, locate Commander Morag
and Lieutenant Uhnari.
COMPUTER:
Commander Morag
is in his quarters.
Lieutenant Uhnari is not
aboard the Enterprise.
Where did she go?
COMPUTER:
Lieutenant Uhnari transported
to relay station 47
at 1830 hours.
You get Morag.
I'm going to the station.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
( exhaling )
Geordi?
I can see you.
Oh...
and I can... feel you.
( breathing deeply )
Do not move.
What is this?
You will come with me.
You've never been
as close to someone
as you are about to be.
Think of me.
( door opening )
Step away from him,
Lieutenant.
What are you doing,
Commander?
That may not be
Lieutenant Uhnari.
What?
What are you saying?
Step away... now.
Medical officer's log,
supplemental.
Commander Morag
and Lieutenant Uhnari
are being kept
under close observation.
So far, no sign of coalescent
behavior has surfaced.
Aquiel and Morag
will be transferred
to a secure medical facility
on Starbase 12.
Maybe we'll know more
by the time we get there.
Yeah. Right.
It could be Morag.
We don't know
for sure.
Sure.
Get some rest.
You've had a rough
couple of days.
Thanks.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
Computer...
display the engineering duty
roster for the next three days.
( growling playfully )
Maura, come on.
Not now.
Maura, I said not now.
Come on,
give me a break here!
Not...!
Go lay down!
( resonant growl )
Maura?
( roaring )
( sighs )
LA FORGE:
Maybe the reason
you don't remember
anything that happened
after Rocha attacked you
is that the coalescing
process had begun.
Thank you.
Remember when you said
you felt like the memories
had been drained
right out of you?
Well, that's probably
exactly what
was going on.
Then maybe I did
take the phaser.
Well, whatever happened,
at least you got away
before the process
took hold.
So, he turned on Maura.
Right.
Well...
what now?
I guess I'll be going
to Starbase 212
for reassignment.
You know,
I had a conversation
with Chief Pendleton
in communications
and there's an opening
for a level-2 specialist.
Really?
Oh, I'm sure
the waiting list is so long
I'd be gray
before I got here.
I could put in
a good word.
It's an appealing offer,
but I think I'd rather
get here on my own merits.
Don't be surprised if you
see my name on that list.