( gasping )
( groans )
Computer,
lights.
turn on the lights.
( groans )
( gasps )
Space,
the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Good,
you're awake.
Who are you?
Please, Counselor,
there is little time.
The Commander will be
calling for you at any moment.
Where am I?
You are aboard
the imperial Romulan
warbird Khazara.
I am Subcommander N'vek.
Warbird?
I-- I was at the, uh...
neuropsychology
seminar at Bokara VI.
The last thing
I remember was
returning
to my quarters.
I was attacked.
I felt a hypospray.
It was necessary.
I could not be certain
you would come
voluntarily.
Oh, God, my head's
still spinning.
There are drugs
in your system,
but they've nearly
dissipated.
The disorientation
will soon pass.
Why have you
brought me here?
Listen to me
carefully.
You are no longer
Deanna Troi.
You are Major Rakal
of the Tal Shiar--
the Imperial
intelligence.
Commander Toreth--
Am I a prisoner?
There is no time
to explain everything.
You must listen.
Commander Toreth will
want to know your mission.
Tell her nothing.
Simply instruct her
to proceed
to the Kaleb sector.
Heading 102 mark 4.
The Kaleb sector?
Repeat it.
Heading 102 mark 4.
( sighs ):
And she'll take
orders from me?
You are an officer
of the Tal Shiar.
She will obey you,
but do not push her too far.
FEMALE:
Subcommander N'vek,
we are approaching
the loading point.
Bring our guest
to the bridge.
Yes, Commander,
immediately.
Please, we must hurry.
I'm not going anywhere
until you tell me
what's going on.
You are a Starfleet officer
disguised as a Romulan.
Unless you trust me
and do exactly as I have said,
Toreth will discover you,
and you will be killed.
How do I know I won't
be killed anyway?
Your only chance
to get off this ship alive
is to do as I say.
You are an empath.
You would know if
I am lying-- am I?
No.
Then let us go see
the commander.
Orbit established,
Commander.
Commence loading
of the cargo.
Notify me when
the transfer is complete.
Yes, sir.
Commander,
may I present
Major Rakal
of the Tal Shiar.
This is
Commander Toreth.
Attend to your station.
Why are you here
without your guards?
Well?
The mission is
one of utmost secrecy.
I could not risk
bringing guards.
And what exactly
is the nature
of this clandestine
assignment?
I cannot reveal that.
Oh?
Why not?
I'm under orders.
You don't act like
a member of the Tal Shiar.
How long have you been
with intelligence?
Several months.
Ahh.
( console beeping )
Commander, cargo is
on board and secure.
Tell me--
is there a reason
why the commander of the ship
is kept ignorant of its cargo?
TROI:
I don't know what you mean.
I have been ordered
to take on cargo,
but its contents
are unknown to me.
Does that seem wise?
I am responsible for
the safety of this ship
and its crew.
How do I know this cargo is
safe to transport?
I'm sure it is safe.
Otherwise, it would
not have been loaded.
Ahh.
The Tal Shiar is
deeply concerned
for the safety
and the well-being
of the military.
I'm sure that
every person
on the bridge of this ship
could offer testimony
about personal experiences
with the Tal Shiar,
but I doubt that many could
recall those encounters
as tender and caring.
So I must ask you
to forgive me, Major,
if I hesitate to accept
your assurances
that that cargo presents
no danger to my crew.
I intend to open
those containers.
That cargo is the property
of the Tal Shiar.
You will not touch it.
On whose authority?
Mine. And if you
do not wish to undergo
another "personal experience"
with the Tal Shiar,
I suggest
you not question me again.
Now, proceed on course
bearing 102 mark 4
to the Kaleb sector.
Why should we go
to the Kaleb sector?
It's virtually deserted.
Because those are
your orders.
Pilot, set course.
102 mark 4.
Warp six.
PILOT:
Yes, Commander.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46519.1.
We have arrived
at Research Station 75
to take on a rather
unique passenger,
one whose homecoming will
undoubtedly be difficult.
The man acted
dishonorably.
He is a traitor.
He risked his life
to get here.
Spent two weeks
alone in a scout ship.
That does not excuse
his original actions.
Well, maybe he finally
realized he made a mistake.
It's 20 years
too late.
Energize.
Ensign Deseve, by order
of Starfleet command,
I am placing you
under arrest for treason.
I understand.
After Dr. Crusher
declares you medically fit,
you will be confined
to your quarters
until a court-martial
can be convened.
Find some
civilian clothes.
I don't want to see you
in that uniform.
Yes, sir.
Commander?
I must speak
with Captain Picard.
He's a busy man.
Please.
It's important.
Urgent.
I'll tell him.
Commander.
At ease.
It's Captain,
actually.
Of course.
Um... sorry, sir.
You said it was important
that I see you.
Yes, Captain.
I have a message
from Ambassador Spock.
He said it involves
further...
"cowboy diplomacy."
He said you would
understand.
There's a Corvallen
freighter arriving
in the Kaleb sector
in the next 12 hours.
Spock wants you to...
rendezvous?--
with that ship,
bring its cargo back
to Federation space.
What kind of cargo?
He said it was...
important...
to the future
of the Romulans
and the Federation.
And you have returned in order
to give me this message?
Partly.
In order to know whether
Ambassador Spock's message
is being delivered
accurately,
I need to understand
something about the messenger.
I was ready
to come back.
Romulus had...
lost its appeal.
Yet, at one time
you found something
very appealing
about it.
The Romulans are
very moral, Captain.
They have
an absolute certainty
about what is right
and what is wrong,
who is a friend
and who is an enemy--
a strict moral compass,
which provides them with
a clarity of purpose.
At one time, I found
their sense of purpose,
their passion
and commitment,
to be very
compelling.
But not anymore.
As I've grown older,
I realize that
clarity of purpose is
a more ambiguous matter
than I had thought
in my youth.
Commander Riker,
set a course
for the Kaleb sector.
Warp factor eight.
RIKER:
Aye, aye, sir.
You may wait outside.
Make certain
we're not disturbed.
They're terrified of me.
The purpose of the Tal Shiar
is to ensure loyalty.
To defy them is to invite
imprisonment or death.
I think it's time
you told me
what this is
all about.
That is why
I called you here.
These are
the cargo containers
we brought
on board earlier.
What's in it?
He's alive in stasis.
Who is it?
Vice-Proconsul M'ret
of the Imperial Senate
and his two top aides.
M'ret?
He's one
of the highest-ranking members
of the Romulan
government.
His defection will be
a profound blow to Romulus.
Why is he doing this?
M'ret had questioned
the repressive activities
of the government
and was in danger
of being imprisoned.
He is willing
to take this risk
in order to protest
Romulan policy
and support
the dissident movement.
You are part
of Ambassador Spock's
underground movement.
Yes.
If we're able
to deliver M'ret safely,
Spock is hopeful that we can
establish an escape route
for thousands of dissidents
who live in fear of their lives.
Now you realize
why we are willing
to go to such
extraordinary lengths--
even kidnapping you--
to make sure we succeed.
You've given me the identity
of a Tal Shiar officer.
Is there a real
Major Rakal?
There was.
She was killed so that
you could take her place.
Only a member
of the Tal Shiar
would have the authority
to alter a ship's mission.
Why me? You could
have found a Romulan
to play this role.
Yes, for the first
part of the plan,
but if anything
goes wrong,
we will need
a Starfleet officer.
Why?
There's no need
to go into that
unless it becomes
necessary.
For your own sake,
Counselor,
the less you know
about the specifics
of this plan,
the better.
What is your plan?
When we reach
the Kaleb sector,
we will rendezvous with
a Corvallen freighter.
You will take
these containers
into their ship
and accompany them
back to Starfleet
headquarters.
The Corvallens are
mercenaries.
Do they know what's
in these containers?
No, they were hired
simply to take you
to Federation space.
Very well.
We are due in
the wardroom shortly.
The senior officers
always dine together.
I'll go to my quarters--
I think it would be best
if I stayed out of the way
of the commander.
No, you will be
expected to attend.
I'll go ahead.
Follow me after
a few moments.
Commander Toreth
must not feel
that anything is unusual.
( door opens, closes )
We had been told that
the Klingon outpost
was undefended.
So when their
warships decloaked...
they took us completely
by surprise.
The Klingons managed
to destroy half my squadron
before we even opened fire,
but when we did... ha!
They were
no match for us.
I destroyed
their flagship myself.
I received
the Sotarek citation
for my actions
that day.
The intelligence officer
in charge of that
mission was executed.
Major.
Welcome to our table.
Commander.
I suggest you try
the viinerine.
It's quite good.
I realize that
it's nothing
compared to what you're
accustomed to on Romulus,
but you could at least
try the viinerine.
I've smelled better viinerine
on prison ships.
No doubt.
Tell me, Major.
Where did you train?
The Intelligence Academy
or the Imperial War
College?
The Academy.
Oh.
So you must know
Commander Konsab.
I know of him.
I assume you sat in
military history
with him.
Yes.
Tell me, Major...
what do you think
about his theories
on the differences
between the military
and the Tal Shiar?
Which aspects are you
referring to?
Oh, come now, Major.
Surely you attended
his classes regularly.
It was Konsab's
main theme.
Do you have a point
to make, Commander?
If so,
it has escaped me.
Commander Konsab...
believes that,
in order to function,
military officers have
to trust each other.
The Tal Shiar,
on the other hand,
trust no one.
They expect deception,
so they always find it.
Your opinion
of the Tal Shiar
is quite clear,
Commander.
I hope so.
We ensure the loyalty
of the people.
Do you believe the Empire
would be better off
without our protection?
Protection? From what?
How was the Empire
threatened
by the words
of an old man,
a devoted citizen who merely
tried to speak his mind?
How did the Tal Shiar
protect the Empire
by dragging him,
my father, out of his home
in the middle
of the night?
Clearly, your father
was a traitor.
No.
He was just
an idealistic old man.
I never saw him again.
I don't need
your devotion, Commander,
just your obedience.
And that's all you have.
MALE VOICE:
Commander, sensors
are picking up
an unidentified ship
on an intercept course.
What is the configuration?
It appears to be
a freighter, Commander.
Hail them.
Visual.
Commander,
we are glad to see you.
We are prepared to transfer
your cargo, as agreed.
And with whom
do you have this agreement?
Our arrangements were made
with Major Rakal.
You may rest assured,
your cargo will be
taken safely
to its destination.
We will transmit coordinates
for you to beam it aboard.
He's lying.
Very well.
They have no intention
of keeping their word.
Are you certain?
Yes.
Why did you destroy
that vessel?!
I beg forgiveness,
Commander,
but Major Rakal
ordered me to fire.
The Corvallen freighter
has been completely
destroyed, Commander.
There are
no survivors.
I demand
an explanation.
How many people were
on that ship?
Approximately
18 people, sir.
I don't care
if there were 18 or 800.
On this ship, I give
the command to fire, Major.
You have no right.
This gives me
the right!
Even you eventually will
have to answer to someone.
You will be held
accountable.
I have been given broad
discretionary powers.
Subcommander N'vek acted
under my authority--
the authority
of the Tal Shiar.
I assure you, this action
will not be questioned.
I will, nonetheless,
make an entry in my log
that I am not responsible
for those 18 lives
and that I deplore
their loss.
Do whatever you feel
is necessary.
In the meantime,
we must protect ourselves.
Engage
the cloaking device.
And what are
my orders now, Major?
Hold position
and wait.
There is no sign
of the freighter, sir.
We are the only ship
in the area.
Ensign, verify
our position.
We are holding at
the coordinates
specified by
Ensign Deseve, sir.
Anything on
long-range sensors?
Sensors indicate
no other ships
within three
light-years.
Could this have
been a hoax?
That's one possibility.
Mr. Worf, bring Ensign Deseve
to my ready room.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Deseve,
you promised me
a freighter with
an important cargo.
The only thing here
is empty space.
Do you have
an explanation?
I don't understand.
Captain,
he has deceived us.
No, I was told
that the ship
would be at
these coordinates.
You said...
that the message
came directly
from Ambassador Spock.
Yes.
Well...
not exactly.
And what does that mean?
Someone else relayed
the message to me,
but he said Spock
spoke directly to him.
I trust the man
who spoke to me.
He would not have lied.
Was he a Romulan?
Yes, he's a member
of the underground--
a dissident.
He risks his life
to work with those
who want a different
future for Romulus.
Captain, he could be
leading us into a trap.
No, that is not so.
It would be risky
to set a trap here
so close
to Federation space,
but the fact remains,
here we are...
there is no freighter.
Did your contact tell you
anything else
that might be helpful?
The freighter is
an old Antares-class vessel
with limited speed
and range.
It couldn't have taken on
its cargo more than a day ago
which means
it must be within
15 light-years
of here.
Why didn't you mention
this earlier?
It didn't seem necessary.
And, on Romulus, you learn
not to volunteer information.
It's a hard habit
to break.
Well, maybe now would be
a good time to start.
Follow me,
gentlemen.
Our plan has collapsed.
Our plan?
What about the people
on that freighter?
Why did you fire?
There was no alternative.
You told me
they couldn't be trusted.
If I let them live,
the whole mission
would be in jeopardy.
18 people lost
their lives.
Don't lecture me,
Counselor.
A number of people
have died in order
to carry out
this mission.
Believe me, those 18
won't be the last.
I'm sorry,
but I can't
dismiss those lives
so easily.
Fine, agonize
all you want,
but don't let it get
in the way of our plan.
You don't have
a plan anymore.
You remember I told you
if anything went wrong,
we would need
a Starfleet officer.
There is a Starfleet base
on Draken IV.
It is two days away
at maximum warp.
That's where
we're going.
In a Romulan ship?
Yes.
It's your job
to order Toreth
to proceed into
Federation territory.
We'll never get through
the gravitic sensor nets.
We will, if you provide
the correct access codes.
Do you really think this has
a chance of succeeding?
If you have
another idea,
I'll be happy
to consider it.
TROI:
You will plot a course
for the Draken system.
Oh, you can't be serious.
Draken IV was
the freighter's destination.
I ordered
the freighter destroyed
because I recognized
the captain--
a known Federation spy.
Now we must deliver
the cargo ourselves.
We...?
I do not intend
to explain myself
to you.
You will set
a course...
In order to reach Draken,
we will have to travel
through Federation space
for nearly 20 hours.
That is not a problem.
Contrary
to the propaganda
that your superiors
would have us believe,
Starfleet is neither
weak nor foolish.
The chances of us
reaching Draken undetected
are not good.
We will be cloaked.
Oh, the cloaking device
does not always
make us invulnerable.
And you would know that
if you had spent any time at all
in the field.
The Federation has
littered its borders
with subspace
listening posts
with gravitic sensors.
They may even have
a tachyon detection grid
in operation, in which case,
they will know that we're there.
If we are discovered
in Federation territory,
it will be interpreted
as an act of war.
The Tal Shiar has
obtained access codes
to the sensor nets.
I will provide them
if necessary.
That will be
no guarantee
that we will escape
undetected.
Your cowardice does not befit
a Romulan soldier.
People blame the military
for the wars that
we are asked to fight,
but I think it is
your kind, Major,
that will be
the death of us all.
TORETH:
Plot a course for
the Draken system.
Course plotted, sir.
Prepare for warp.
Commander, sensors are
picking up a vessel.
Our cloaking device
is still engaged.
They have not
detected us.
Activate viewscreen.
Enlarge.
It is the Enterprise,
Commander.
Well, Major,
it appears your suspicions
about the freighter
were correct after all.
The Federation has come
in search of its spies.
Status.
They are scanning the debris
of the freighter.
Shield levels normal.
Weapons systems
not active.
They are not prepared
for battle, sir.
Well, they weren't
expecting to find us here,
and I see no reason to alter
that perception.
The radiation from
the debris field
could make our cloak detectable
if we engage warp engines.
Proceed at
maneuvering speed.
One moment,
Commander.
We should hold
our position
until the Enterprise
has left the area.
We cannot risk detection.
Even if we are detected,
they cannot track us
once we go to warp.
We have not established
their intentions.
Their intentions are
obvious, Major,
and are of
no concern to us.
Proceed on course,
maneuvering engines only.
Go to warp when we're clear
of the debris field.
Yes, Commander.
We should clear
the field in 27 minutes.
You will keep me informed
of our progress.
It is not wise to challenge
the Tal Shiar, Commander.
I will not let her
tell me how to run my ship.
DATA:
It appears to be
the remains of a ship.
My analysis
indicates that it was
an Antares-class
freighter.
That's the ship
we were supposed to meet.
Could there have been
some kind of malfunction--
a reactor core breach?
I do not
believe so, sir.
That would not be consistent
with the debris pattern.
However, sensors indicate
extremely high levels
of residual antiprotons.
Romulan
disruptor fire.
Correct.
And based on
the antiproton decay,
I would estimate
the incident occurred
within the last
4.3 hours.
Then the Romulans could
still be in the vicinity.
Red alert.
Shields at maximum.
Whatever that
freighter was carrying,
they certainly didn't
want it to reach us.
Are you sure you don't
know what it was?
No, sir, I swear it.
All we have here
are questions.
Mr. Data, continue
with your scan.
We have to get a message
to the Enterprise.
That's impossible.
It's the perfect
opportunity.
The Enterprise is nearby.
If we can communicate with them,
they might be able to help us.
Counselor, this ship is
traveling under cloak.
All of our
electromagnetic
emissions are
being monitored.
Any attempt at
communication whatsoever,
and we would be
discovered instantly.
It could not succeed.
We must continue
to Draken IV.
That is
the safest course.
Is there anything
you can do to the ship
or to the cloaking device
that would let
the Enterprise track us?
Track us?
No.
We want to get into Federation
territory undetected.
What we want is to get
the dissidents to safety.
Now, answer the question--
is there a way?
If there were,
I wouldn't do it.
Yes, you will.
Counselor.
We're not playing it
your way anymore, N'vek!
I've been kidnapped,
surgically altered,
put in danger--
I've gone along
with all your plans.
Now you are going
to listen to me!
You find a way to let
the Enterprise track us,
or I will go to Toreth
and tell her
I've discovered
you're a traitor!
I'll have you
ejected into space!
Is that clear,
Subcommander?!
( sighs )
There is
one possibility.
In order for a ship
to remain undetectable
while cloaked,
the radiative emissions
from the warp engines
must be precisely
balanced.
The ship's engineer is
a sympathizer.
He may be able
to slightly misalign
one of the nullifier cores.
It would create...
a small magnetic
disruption in space
whenever we were
in motion.
Good. Do it.
The effect would only
be intermittent.
They might not
even detect it.
If it's the best
we can do,
we have to try it.
Anything more would be
immediately registered
on the bridge.
Even this slight
misalignment
may be detected.
It's a risk
we have to take.
You're the one that outlined
the stakes to me, N'vek.
Are you getting
squeamish now
just because
things are getting
a little more
dangerous?
Sensors are picking up
a polarized
magnetic distortion
to our portside.
Analysis.
The distortion is
extremely weak.
It appears to be
moving slowly.
It... it is gone, sir.
Gone?
The distortion
no longer registers
on our instruments.
Could this distortion
be caused by a cloaked ship?
Unknown, sir.
Our understanding
of Romulan technology
is still limited.
Captain?
Romulan ships use
a forced quantum singularity
as a power source.
If that system is not
functioning perfectly
or is damaged
even slightly,
it might show
through the cloak
as a magnetic disturbance
of some kind.
The distortion has
reappeared, sir.
Bearing 337 mark 10.
It...
it has disappeared
again, sir.
Mr. Deseve,
in your opinion,
is it possible that
we're picking up
a cloaked
Romulan ship?
It's a strong
possibility, sir.
( sighs )
Mr. Data,
continue your scan.
Ensign, link
navigational control
to Mr. Data's console
and plot a course
for that distortion.
Commander,
the Enterprise is underway.
Good, what is
their course?
They're heading
for us, sir.
What?
They appear to be on
an intercept course.
What is the status
of our cloaking device?
Is there a malfunction
of any kind?
PILOT:
Cloaking device
functioning correctly, sir.
All shipboard emissions
within proper range.
TORETH:
Maintain full sensor scans.
Commander.
The Enterprise may
simply be engaged
in search operations.
Perhaps.
Where is it now,
Mr. Data?
DATA:
It has disappeared
once again, sir.
I believe it may have
been coming to a halt.
Stop engines.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
If this is
a Romulan ship,
will it stay in position
until we leave?
I don't think so, sir.
A Romulan commander's
instinct
would be to attack.
Engage maneuvering
engines.
Forward 0.1.
Take us directly
under their hull.
Yes, Commander.
What are you doing?
It seems that
the Enterprise
can track us even though
we are cloaked.
I intend to find out
if they can or they cannot.
N'vek, ready
attack procedure.
Sir, disruptors are
standing by.
Ready to disengage cloak.
We cannot risk
an engagement here.
Considering the nature
of our mission,
I would have preferred
to have avoided it as well,
but I see no other
alternative.
What do you
intend to do?
We will pass as close
as we possibly can.
If they do have
the ability to track us,
they will move
to avoid a collision.
If they do...
I will destroy them.
Sir, the magnetic distortion
has reappeared.
Bearing and speed?
It appears to be
moving toward us,
closing slowly.
Its bearing indicates
a possible collision course.
RIKER:
Time to impact?
I am unable to get
a precise measurement.
However, I would estimate
impact within 90 seconds.
It doesn't
make any sense.
Why would they
run into us?
If they were, why would
they do it at full speed?
I don't know, sir.
The Romulans will sometimes
make suicide attacks
but only as
a last resort.
There's no reason
for it here.
DATA:
Time to impact
approximately 60 seconds.
We don't have the luxury
to speculate.
Back us away from
the disruption, Ensign--
one-half impulse.
Aye, sir.
They are moving away,
commander.
Prepare attack sequence.
All sections report ready
for battle, Commander.
Disruptors
fully charged.
Disengage cloak
on my command.
Prepare to fire...
Disregard that order.
What?
I do not authorize
this attack.
You will cease battle
operations immediately.
I do not need
your authorization
to attack, Major--
this is my ship.
How typical of the military
to resort to brute force
when discretion is
required.
The Enterprise has
demonstrated that
it can track us.
They must be
destroyed.
Yes, they can track us,
so, if we attack them,
they will return fire,
and since
we have no shields
when we're cloaked,
they will destroy us.
Are you questioning
my ability to command?
You are not fit
to command.
Step down.
Step down, or I will
have you removed.
Do you think anyone here
will listen to you?
If any one of you
defies the Tal Shiar,
you will not bear
the punishment alone.
Your families,
all of them,
will be there
beside you.
I am now commander
of this ship-- you will
take orders from me
and no one else.
Remove Commander Toreth
from her station.
If she resists,
shoot her.
Commander...
please step down.
Remove her weapon.
Now, Commander...
watch and learn.
In order
to defeat your enemy,
you must first
understand them.
The Federation wishes
to avoid war at all costs,
so I will offer them
a diplomatic solution--
get them to lower
their shields...
and then...
destroy them.
Captain,
we are being hailed.
PICARD:
On screen.
I am Major Rakal
of the Tal Shiar.
I'm Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
How can we be of help?
A Corvallen freighter has been
destroyed not far from here.
We have detected
the residual effects
of disruptor fire.
Can you shed
any light on this?
A regrettable incident,
Captain.
The freighter
was fired upon
by the former commander
of this vessel.
I have now taken control,
and, I assure you,
there will be
no more attacks.
Still, there was
considerable loss of life.
Captain, we do not want
to exaggerate this incident.
You and I can
discuss it calmly.
We can defuse it before
it becomes inflated.
I agree.
I will come
onto your ship.
Please lower your shields
and prepare to beam me aboard.
Very well.
Mr. Worf,
lock onto Major Rakal.
Transport on my command.
Aye, sir.
Thank you.
What's she doing
on that ship?
I don't know,
Number One...
but she needs our help
to get back.
Mr. Worf, keep that lock on her,
no matter what happens.
Yes, sir.
Lower shields.
Their shields are
dropping.
Activate forward
disruptor array.
Fire when ready.
Yes, Major.
Firing.
WORF:
Captain,
they have fired on us.
Shields up.
Stand by phasers.
Damage report.
WORF:
we sustained a direct hit,
but the damage was
negligible.
The disruptor
had almost no power.
This is Proconsul M'ret
and his aides.
They're part
of the underground movement.
They're in stasis.
Medical team to the bridge.
MALE VOICE:
Aye, sir.
Where's Deanna?
Disruptors were
ineffective.
The Enterprise was
not damaged.
They have reestablished
full shields.
I am reading a malfunction
in the forward disruptor array.
The power system is
destabilized.
You're lying.
The disruptor beam has
been purposely sabotaged
to conceal
a transporter beam within.
Quickly, pilot.
Locate transport
coordinates.
What have you done?
PILOT:
The transporter beam originated
in our cargo bay.
Something was transported
from there to the Enterprise.
So, Major...
the mysterious cargo
brought on board
by Major Rakal
of the Tal Shiar
has been transported
to the Starfleet vessel.
I see two traitors
in our midst.
So, Major...
now that you can
no longer take refuge
behind the shield
of the Tal Shiar,
it's time to answer
a few questions.
What was in those
cargo containers?
Well, no matter.
We will soon know
all that we need to know...
and then we will
execute you.
Pilot, drop shields
and cloak the ship.
Prepare to go
to warp.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, now.
Counselor.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Let's get you
to sick bay.
Ensign, get us out of here--
warp nine.
Aye, sir.
Well,
that about does it.
How does it feel to have
your own face back?
Just right.
Thank you.
The men you helped rescue
are all safe.
Proconsul M'ret is deeply
grateful for your help.
The thanks should
go to N'vek.
He sacrificed himself
to save them... and me.
Well, thanks
to the two of you,
the way has been paved for
further rescue operations.
N'vek's efforts
and his sacrifice
were not in vain.