Bring the stasis
units in here
and have them on line.
MAN: Yes, Doctor.
Tell Dr. Selar she
can use Ward Three
for the ambulatory patients,
and I'll stay here--
MAN: Transporter Room Four
to Sick Bay.
They're coming in now.
Acknowledged.
Stand clear and be ready.
MAN: All right.
Let's go, let's go.
Get him up here.
What happened?
The Lenarians
attacked us
outside of the
conference room.
CRUSHER:
He's in cardiac arrest.
Connect the pulmonary
support unit.
He's got internal
hemorrhaging.
The bioregulator of
his artificial heart
has been fused,
he's got liver
and spleen damage.
What kind of weapon
caused this?
A compressed teryon beam.
40 cc's inaprovaline.
The activity in the
isocortex is falling.
Cortical stimulators.
Now.
Again.
His respiratory system
is shutting down.
The levels in the isocortex
are still falling.
Damn!
Prepare a cordrazine series...
Welcome to the afterlife,
Jean-Luc.
You're dead.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Q, what is going on?
I told you.
You're dead,
this is the afterlife,
and I'm God.
You are not God.
Blasphemy! You're lucky
I don't cast you out
or smite you or something.
The bottom line is
your life ended
about five minutes ago
under the inept ministrations
of Dr. Beverly Crusher.
No.
I am not dead...
because I refuse
to believe that the
afterlife is run by you.
The universe is not
so badly designed.
Very well.
If you really require
more evidence of your
postmortem status,
I guess I'll just
have to provide you some.
MAN:
Jean-Luc, I told you
not to go running off
to that academy.
Father.
I told you
that Starfleet
would bring you to a bad end,
but you wouldn't listen.
Now, look at you--
dead before your time.
Q, enough of this.
Enough what?
Why couldn't you have listened?
Didn't you know
that I was working for
your best interests?
Q, stop this!
After all these years,
even now, you manage to
disappoint me, Jean-Luc.
He's not the only one
who would like to have
a word with you.
WOMAN 1: Why, Jean-Luc?
Why did you do it?
WOMAN 2: Captain, there are
still people down there,
we can't abandon...
MAN 1: There must be
some other way, Captain,
some other choice
than firing on them.
MAN 2: I'm warning you.
If you continue on this...
MAN 3: A direct hit, sir.
The ship is destroyed.
These are the voices
of all the people
you've killed
throughout the years.
Whom I've killed?
What do you mean?
Death has made you a
little dim, Jean-Luc.
These are the voices
of all the people
who have died...
through your actions
or your inactions.
Now, if you have any words
of apology or regret,
I believe
they're all listening.
They're a surly bunch, actually,
so I wouldn't drag
this out too long.
I have no intention of
performing for your amusement.
This is not for me,
this is for you, Jean-Luc.
This is your opportunity to make
peace with your sordid past.
I find it hard
to believe
that you are doing this
for the benefit of my soul.
Well, now that you've shuffled
off the mortal coil,
we're free to spend a
little time together.
"A little time together."
How much?
Eternity.
Now, you're sure
you have no regrets
or feelings of guilt about
your former life?
I mean, I can't
have you whining
and complaining
through time.
If I'm really dead,
then my only regret
is dying and
finding you here.
You wound me,
Jean-Luc.
After all, I was not
the cause of your death.
This was.
Is that--
Your artificial heart.
You might have lived
if you had a real one
instead of this unreliable
piece of technology.
By the way, how did you
lose yours, anyway?
A mistake.
Is that a regret I hear?
I regret many things
from those days.
Really?
( loud grunting )
( grunting and groaning )
( laughing )
Wasn't very smart of you
to take on three Nausicaans,
was it?
No, it wasn't.
And did I hear a laugh?
It's so unlike you, Jean-Luc,
to have a sense of humor--
especially about getting
stabbed through the back.
I was a different person
in those days--
arrogant,
undisciplined...
with far too much ego
and far too little
wisdom.
I was more like you.
Then you must have been
far more interesting.
Pity you had to change.
The pity is that I had to
be impaled through the back
before I learned
that lesson.
I started that fight
with those Nausicaans.
I started it because...
because I was
young and cocky.
If I'd been more
responsible in those days,
I wouldn't have
needed this heart.
And I wouldn't have died
from a random energy
surge 30 years later.
So, if you had to
do it all over again?
Things would be different.
( laughter )
( clapping )
Bravo, bravo.
Nicely done.
Cortin?
Cortin Zweller?
Yes.
Boy, she must have
hit you pretty hard.
Of course,
you deserved it.
Slowing down there,
Johnny.
You should have seen
that one coming.
Marta Batanides.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm, uh... I'm just a little
disoriented, that's all.
Oh, come on, he's just
playing for sympathy now.
Look, I'm gonna get
something to eat
and head over to the
casino at Bonestell.
You coming?
Uh... I'll catch up
with you there.
You sure you're okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Really, Marta, I'm fine.
Come on, Marty.
I'll bet he's got
another date.
That's it, isn't it?
You are incorrigible.
Attention on deck,
Ensign Picard.
Q.
That's Captain Q
to you, young man.
What is the point of
creating this fantasy?
This is no fantasy,
I assure you.
It's all very real.
You're 21 years old again.
A brash young man,
fresh out of the academy.
I certainly
don't look it.
Well...
to everyone else, you do.
So, Q, I thought you
told me that I was dead.
Now, it seems
that I'm alive.
Oh, you mortals
are so obtuse.
Why do you persist
in believing
that life and death are such
static and rigid concepts?
Why, I can take your life
and give it back to you again
with the snap
of a finger.
Let's say for the moment
that may be true.
What is the purpose
in bringing me here?
You said you regretted a great
many things in your life.
Well, here's a chance
to change some of them.
Change them?
Do you mean, change the past?
Q, even if
you have been able
to bring me back
in time somehow,
surely, you must realize that
any alteration
in this timeline will have
a profound impact
on the future.
Please, spare me your
egotistical musings
on your pivotal
role in history.
Nothing you do
here will cause
the Federation
to collapse
or galaxies to explode.
To be blunt,
you're not that important.
I won't do it.
I won't alter history.
Ah! Very well!
Since you attach
so much importance
to the continuity of time...
I will give you my
personal guarantee
that nothing you do here
will end up hurting anyone
or have an adverse effect on
what you know of as history.
The only thing at stake
here is your life
and your peace of mind.
Now...
whether you
believe me or not,
you are here, and you
have a second chance.
What you choose
to do with it
is entirely up to you.
Do you know
where you are?
Starbase Earhart.
We came here right
after graduation
to await our first
deep space assignments.
That's right.
It's two days before
your unfortunate encounter
with a Nausicaan sword.
You have that long to make
whatever changes you wish.
If you can avoid getting stabbed
through the heart this time--
which I doubt--
I will take you back to what
you think of as the present,
and you will go on
with your life,
with a real heart.
Then I won't die?
Of course, you'll die.
It will just be
at a later time.
What if I don't
avoid the fight?
What if I won't make
the changes?
Then you die
on the table
and we spend
eternity together.
Wonderful.
I'm glad you think so.
I'm curious about
one thing... Johnny.
Why did that rather
attractive woman
strike you just now--
was it something you said?
Her name was Corlina,
and... I'd arranged to
take her out today.
And then she
discovered that...
I had already made
a second date
with another woman
called, um...
...Penny.
And Corlina was
naturally upset.
I had no idea
you were such a cad.
I'm impressed.
Computer, what is
the time right now?
COMPUTER:
1611 hours.
In fact, Penny is waiting
for me... right now.
Well, carry on.
PENNY: Well, you're
awfully quiet today.
What happened to that
dashing young Ensign
from last night, hmm?
The one with
the winning smile
and the smooth talk
about my eyes?
( both chuckle )
I'm-- I'm just a little
more contemplative.
Hmm, and what are you
contemplating?
Penny, um...
do you think we could
just talk for a while?
I hardly know
anything about you.
Where you're from,
what your interests are,
your last name.
I come from Rigel,
my last name is Muroc,
and I like men in uniform.
I think that's
enough talking.
What's wrong?
I don't look as attractive
to you as I did last night?
No, no, not at all.
I think you're a
very handsome woman.
"Handsome."
That's something you
say to old ladies.
You're certainly
not an old lady.
I didn't want your pity.
( blowing )
Penny for your thoughts.
You never told me
you were such a ladies' man.
I wasn't.
I was a puerile adolescent
who allowed himself
to be led by his hormones,
instead of his head.
( applause and cheering )
Looks like your friends
know how to have fun.
You ought to take lessons.
Excuse me.
( indistinct voices )
MAN:
How 'bout a bank shot?
He's winning.
Of course.
I thought you
had a date.
She... decided to leave.
You're getting old,
Johnny.
( cheering )
Thank you.
Thank you all.
Very, very nice.
I think you should
forget about Starfleet
and play dom-jot
for a living.
Oh, this is nothing.
A little trigonometry,
some minor wrist action.
Now, barokie,
there's a game.
NAUSICAAN:
Human!
Play dom-jot, human?
I think I could
be persuaded
to play one more game.
( growls )
Corey, don't play him.
Why?
It'll cause trouble.
He's a Nausicaan.
They can get very
ill-tempered if they lose.
So can I.
No, Corey,
listen to me.
This is a big mistake.
Don't play him.
What's gotten into you?
Let's go.
I see you found your
Nausicaan friend.
You seem un-impaled so far.
I'm sorry to
disappoint you.
( chuckles )
MAN: Get him, Corey.
Looks good.
Look at that, yeah!
Ensign Zweller seems
to be doing well.
He's gonna lose.
The Nausicaan
is cheating.
Really?
I'm beginning to like
these Nausicaans.
If history repeats itself,
Corey will figure it
out later tonight,
and then he'll
want revenge.
And will you help
your best friend
avenge this injustice?
I did last time.
( sighs )
I rigged the table
so that he would win
in a rematch.
Picard, you cheated?
I'm impressed.
It was a stupid mistake.
The Nausicaan didn't
take kindly to losing,
nor his friends.
They were outraged.
They wanted a fight.
I gave them one.
That's a beautiful story.
It gets you right here,
doesn't it?
( speaks Nausicaan )
( growls )
( laughing )
( applause and cheering )
Dom-jot.
Human play dom-jot.
( Nausicaan laughing )
I've played a lot of dom-jot
in a lot of places,
and I've never seen the balls
roll that well for anyone.
MARTA:
So, he was cheating?
COREY: I'll bet you
that he had some sort
of magnetic
device in his belt.
It was controlling
the balls.
That's terrible.
We gotta get even.
What'd you have in mind?
Well, we can do to him
what he did to us-- cheat.
Only this time,
we rig the table
so his device will
backfire on him.
Corey, that won't
solve anything.
It'll teach him that
he can't go around
cheating
Starfleet officers.
All it'll do is provoke him.
And provoking a Nausicaan
is not a good idea.
I can handle him.
What if he's not alone?
What if he brings some of his
Nausicaan friends with him?
Well, then I guess that's
when I'm gonna have to depend
on my friends to
help me out.
Oh, Corey, there's got to be
a better way to handle this.
When did you start backing
away from a good fight?
Look, Corey, we're--
we're not cadets anymore.
We're officers.
We should start to set a
higher standard for ourselves.
It was a good idea,
but let's just
forget it, okay?
He'll get over it.
I hope so.
What?
Nothing.
I-it's just you'd usually
be the one plotting revenge.
Huh... yes...
that would be more in
character, wouldn't it?
Much, but I
always suspected
you had a hidden streak of
responsibility somewhere.
Perhaps it's just that
I'm getting older.
Maybe these bars
are just starting
to feel a little
heavy, Ensign.
Ensign Picard and
Ensign Batanides.
Sounds weird,
doesn't it?
It's gonna take some
getting used to.
It's too bad we can't
get used to it together.
Well... the three
of us, I mean.
Oh, of course.
( door chimes )
Come.
Flowers.
Is there a "John-Luck
Pick-erd" here?
From one of your
conquests, no doubt.
I guess some things
aren't gonna change.
( door opens, closes )
Did I interrupt
anything sordid, I hope?
No, Q, you did not.
Pity.
She's quite attractive.
We were friends, nothing more.
Is that another
regret I hear?
My, my...
We're simply riddled
with regrets about our
youth, now, aren't we?
My friendship with Marta is
not something that I regret.
But you wish
it had been more
than just a friendship,
now, don't you?
Well... maybe you
can change all that.
Q, what is it you want?
I thought you'd like to know
that Mr. Zweller's decided
not to take your advice.
He's in the Bonestell
Facility right now
rigging the table
to beat the Nausicaan.
I guess you weren't
that persuasive.
Corey...
Ow!
Johnny, don't sneak
up on me like that.
I thought you were
the gambling foreman.
I'm sorry.
I'm glad you're here.
Hand me that
magna-spanner, huh?
Corey, I'm not
here to help you.
I'm here to stop you from
making a serious mistake.
You sound like my mother.
Cheating the Nausicaans
could have serious
consequences for all of us.
It's a risk we can't
afford to take.
You are my mother.
Well, gee, Mom.
I guess I'll just have to
go tell those Nausicaans
I don't mind
if they cheat me.
This is not
a joke, Corey.
It better be.
Now, I'm gonna
finish my work here.
If you wanna
help me, fine.
If not, I'll see you
back at the starbase.
I said you're
not doing this.
Are you gonna
hit me, Johnny?
No.
But I'll tell the
gambling foreman
someone has been tampering
with his dom-jot table.
All right.
Have it your way,
Ensign Picard.
I just couldn't make
him understand.
At least he did
finally give it up.
Yes, but he didn't
take it very well.
( chuckles )
Oh, you know Corey.
He'll forget all about it
by tomorrow.
I hope you're right,
because he and I were friends
for years after this.
( chuckles )
I mean, um... I hope
that we will be.
You know...
you keep smiling at me.
Well, I've just never
seen you like this before.
You're so... serious.
Do I really seem
that different?
Maybe I'm just not
used to seeing you
in your officer's uniform.
No, it's-- it's more
than that.
You do seem different.
Well, I'm not-- I'm not
complaining or anything.
I think it suits you.
Really?
Yes.
It's very...
attractive.
Johnny...
haven't you ever
thought about us...
getting together?
Yes, I have, actually.
I've thought about it
for a long time.
Why didn't you
ever say so?
I don't know.
And at this moment,
I really have no idea why not.
You've said so now.
Morning, darling.
Feeling a little
jumpy this morning?
Are we... guilty,
perhaps?
I don't feel guilty
about anything, Q.
No?
( imitating Picard )
"We're just friends, Q.
Nothing more."
And we're still friends.
( sighs )
So?
What's next?
I don't know.
What I do know is,
things will be different.
I'm sure.
( quiet conversation )
Good morning.
Johnny...
What's wrong?
Well, this is the
morning after, huh?
Look...
I don't regret anything
that happened last night.
I hope you don't
regret it either.
I don't-- I don't know.
We've been friends for
a long time, and...
and now...
I'm afraid we've ruined
that friendship.
Then perhaps we should...
forget about what
happened, and, uh...
and try to...
I wish I could.
It would make it much easier
to say good-bye tomorrow.
Um...
We're all supposed to,
um, get together later
for a last big night
out on the town
before we all
ship out.
I don't want
you to do anything
that would make you
uncomfortable.
We planned it.
I'll be there.
Q:
Well, let's see.
You've managed to get
slapped by one woman,
a drink thrown in
your face by another,
and alienate your
two best friends.
Doing pretty
well so far.
The only thing
left to avoid
is getting stabbed
through the heart.
( loud crunching )
( indistinct voices )
MAN:
Good shot, good shot.
I think you'll like serving
on board the Ajax.
I hear that Captain Narth
is an excellent officer.
So I hear.
Well...
here's to the class of '27.
Play dom-jot, human?
Give you
a better chance.
Give you a bigger
stick, maybe.
I don't think
we're interested.
They are undari--
cowards.
( Nausicaans laughing )
What did you say?
Coward, like all Starfleet,
you talk and you talk.
But you have
no guramba.
Why don't we find out?
Hey, don't be a fool, Corey.
Look, there are plenty of other
people to play dom-jot with.
Now, just go about
your business.
Maybe I play with her.
Give her good time.
( grunts )
( laughter )
Orcho lok resnik
Starfleet.
I'm sorry, Corey.
He was reaching
for a weapon.
I don't know who
you are anymore,
but you're not my friend.
Good-bye, Johnny.
Congratulations,
mon capitaine.
You did it.
WORF:
Can I help you?
Can I help you,
Mr. Picard?
Mr. Worf...?
This is not for me.
You should take it
to Commander La Forge
in Engineering.
What's happened?
Is something wrong?
I'm not sure.
Mr. Worf, what is my
rank and position?
You are Lieutenant
junior grade
assistant
astrophysics officer.
Are you feeling
all right?
Who is the captain
of this ship?
Captain Thomas Halloway.
Perhaps I should
escort you to Sick Bay.
No, I can find
my own way there.
Thank you, Commander.
Beverly...
something has happened to me.
I'm not sure--
( German accent )
Well, well, well.
What seems to
be the trouble,
Lieutenant Picard?
Q, what have you done?
I've done exactly
as I promised.
I've returned
you to the present.
But this is not the
present I remember.
You said nothing
would change.
Nothing has changed,
Jean-Luc...
except for you.
But then again, that's what
you wanted, wasn't it?
To change the man
you were in your youth.
Well, you did it.
This is the man
you are today.
And you should be happy.
You have a real heart
beating in your chest
and you get to live out the
rest of your life in safety
running tests,
making analyses
and carrying reports
to your superiors.
( low conversation )
Excuse me.
Am I interrupting?
No, not at all.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
I'd like to talk to you
for a moment about my future
on the Enterprise.
Of course,
Lieutenant.
Jean-Luc, isn't it?
Maybe I should go.
No. Please, Counselor.
I would very much like
to hear your thoughts.
First of all--
and I would like you
to be absolutely
straightforward with me--
how would you evaluate me
as an officer?
Well, um...
your performance records
have always been good.
You're thorough,
dedicated...
Steady, reliable.
Punctual.
I see.
What would you say
if I told you that I believed
that I was capable of
being very much more?
Perhaps we should discuss
this at your next evaluation.
I would appreciate it if
we could discuss it now.
You see, I feel that I
would like to move beyond
astrophysics,
to Engineering or...
or security.
Something that might
even lead to command.
Frankly, Lieutenant...
I don't think
that's realistic.
Why?
I really don't think
this is the place to
be discussing this--
Please, this is very
important to me.
I believe that
I can do more.
Hasn't that been
the problem all along?
Throughout your career
you've had lofty goals,
but... you've never
been willing to do
what's necessary
to attain them.
Would that be your evaluation
as well, Commander?
I think I have to agree
with the Counselor.
If you wanna get ahead,
you have to take chances,
stand out in a crowd,
get noticed.
I see.
Now, we don't
wanna lose you.
You're a very good officer.
Just not one
who stands out.
Why don't I talk to
Commander La Forge
in Engineering
and see what we can do.
But, command?
Well...
we'll see.
DATA:
Senior officers, please report
to the captain's ready room.
Acknowledged.
We should talk
about this later.
All right, Q,
that's enough.
You've made your point.
Q?
La Forge to Lieutenant Picard.
I'm still waiting for
that statistical analysis.
I'm on my way, sir.
Main Engineering.
You having a good laugh now, Q?
Does it amuse you to think of me
living out the rest of my life
as a dreary man
in a tedious job?
I gave you something most
mortals never experience--
a second chance at life.
And now, all you
can do is complain?
I can't live out
my days as that person.
That man is bereft
of passion...
and imagination!
That is not who I am!
Au contraire.
He's the person
you wanted to be--
one who was less arrogant and
undisciplined in his youth.
One who was less like me.
The Jean-Luc Picard
you wanted to be--
the one who did not
fight the Nausicaan--
had quite a different career
from the one you remember.
That Picard never had
a brush with death,
never came face-to-face
with his own mortality,
never realized how
fragile life is
or how important
each moment must be.
So, his life never
came into focus.
He drifted through
much of his career
with no plan or agenda,
going from one assignment
to the next,
never seizing
the opportunities
that presented
themselves.
He never led
the away team
on Milika III to save
the ambassador,
or take charge of
the Stargazer's Bridge
when its captain
was killed.
And no one ever
offered him a command.
He learned to
play it safe...
and he never, ever got
noticed by anyone.
You're right, Q.
You gave me
the chance to change
and I took the
opportunity.
But I admit now,
it was a mistake.
Are you asking me
for something, Jean-Luc?
Give me a chance
to put things back
the way they were before.
Before you died
in Sick Bay.
Is that what you want?
I would rather die
as the man I was
than live the life I just saw.
Coward,
like all Starfleet.
You talk and you talk,
but you have no guramba.
( people laughing )
What did you say?
I said...
you are a coward.
That's what I
thought you said.
( grunting )
( yelling )
( groaning )
( laughing )
His vital signs
are stable.
Captain?
Jean-Luc.
You were injured...
but I think you're
going to be all right.
( chuckling )
( chuckling continues )
I still don't know
what to make of it.
Was it a dream?
Or was it one of Q's
elaborate tricks?
A lot of people
who are near death
have strange experiences,
but I have never heard
one so detailed.
And, you know, there's still
part of me that cannot accept
that Q would give
me a second chance,
or that he would demonstrate
so much compassion.
And if it was Q...
I owe him a debt
of gratitude.
In what sense?
It sounds like he
put you through hell.
There are many
parts of my youth
that I'm not proud of.
There were...
loose threads...
untidy parts of me that
I would like to remove.
But when I pulled on
one of those threads,
it unraveled the
tapestry of my life.
I was just trying to imagine
a hell-bent-for-leather
young officer
insulting a Nausicaan
twice his size.
I wish I had a chance to
know that Jean-Luc Picard.
Oh, well,
to tell the truth,
that wasn't the first
run-in that I had
with a couple of
surly Nausicaans.
Really?
Oh, yes.
During my sophomore year,
I was assigned to
training on Morikin VII.
Well, there was a
Nausicaan outpost
on one of the
outlying asteroids.
And one day...