Captain's Log,
Stardate 46578.4:
The Enterprise has arrived
at station Deep Space Nine
to assist
in the reconstruction
of the Bajoran
aqueduct systems
damaged during
the Cardassian occupation.
I should be through with
the water contaminant
analysis in a few hours.
Then I'm going to check out
one of the Holosuites.
They have a relaxation
program here, Jean-Luc,
from Alture VII.
Listen to this.
First, they bathe you
in a protein bath.
Then a cloud of
chromal vapor
carries you into
a meditation chamber.
You should try it.
Well, I'll be too busy
discussing the finer points
of water management
with ten Bajoran
bureaucrats.
And they won't be carrying me
on a cloud of chromal vapor.
Ops.
What is this?
It's pasta al fiorella.
It's one of my favorites.
Don't worry.
You're going to love it.
You know, I really want to take
a look at those Ktaran antiques.
I understand they've got
a 21st-century plasma coil
that's in almost
perfect condition.
( sighs )
I'll have to talk to Chief
O'Brien about these replicators.
Mm-hmm.
Worf, I don't see how
you can eat that stuff.
It tastes like
liquid polymer.
Delicious.
You know, I think I'm going to
try that kiosk on the other side
of the promenade.
It looked like they had
some real food.
Mm-hmm.
DATA: Commander, I am
reading a minor power drain
in the starboard
EPS conduit.
What's causing it?
The problem is
originating in Sick Bay.
There has been
an unauthorized access
into the computer's
bio-imaging systems.
Better check it out.
Aye, sir.
Excuse me.
Do you have authorization
to work in this area?
Come in, come in.
I need a hand with
this field generator.
See if you can boost
the power output to 65%.
I am sorry, but use
of Sick Bay equipment
is limited to
ship's medical personnel.
Ah! Dr. Julian Bashir,
Chief Medical Officer,
Deep Space Nine.
And you are...
Commander...?
Data.
Commander Data.
The synthetic life-form?
Yes.
It's an honor
to meet you, sir.
I've heard
so much about you.
Ah, you must have
a fascinating perspective
into bio-cybernetic
research.
I'd be delighted if we could
discuss the subject sometime.
I would be happy
to do so.
However, I must ask you
to stop your experiment.
Ah, yes.
I realize I should have asked
before using your Sick Bay,
but it would have taken me
days to analyze this device
with the computer I have
on Deep Space Nine.
What type of device
is this?
It was discovered
in the Gamma Quadrant.
I think it must be some
sort of medical instrument.
It appears to employ
plasma inputs.
Well, I'm hoping
it's a medical scanner.
I wanted to use your computer
to find out how it works.
I suggest we take it
to Engineering
and run a complete
circuit-pathway diagnostic.
Splendid.
I must admit,
Commander,
I didn't think you'd be so...
personable.
Klingon.
You are Starfleet Klingon.
I am Lieutenant Worf.
Worf...
son of Mogh?
What of it?
I am Jaglom Shrek,
a man with
information to sell.
You have no information
I could use.
I would not be so sure.
It is about
your father, Mogh.
My father died 25 years ago
at Khitomer.
That is what you believe.
What if I tell you
he is still alive?
PICARD:
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
My father is dead.
No, he's not.
I know where he is.
How is that possible?
I expect to be paid
for my information.
Perhaps we could
negotiate an exchange.
The location of
your father for...
Tell me what you know.
Not all the Klingons
at Khitomer
were killed
during the massacre.
Many were captured
by the Romulans
and placed in a prison camp
on a remote planet.
Your father was among them.
Where is this planet?
Not far from here.
I could give you
the location...
for a price.
A Klingon would rather die
than be taken prisoner.
I should kill you for
spreading lies about my family.
My father was killed
defending Khitomer.
Ensign Lopez, this duty roster
is unacceptable.
Assignments should be listed
in order of priority.
Prepare it again.
I will expect it
no later than 0900 hours.
Dismissed.
Mr. Worf, we'll need to get
your rendezvous schedule
to Commander Rudman
aboard the Merrimack...
I am well aware of
your request, Commander.
Lieutenant,
are you all right?
Yes, sir, I am...
fine.
I will send
your schedule, sir.
Excuse me.
( grunting )
( door chimes )
Enter.
Did the table
do something wrong?
No.
I'm glad you weren't
that hard on Ensign Lopez.
He made a mistake.
The duty roster
was inaccurate.
Would you like to talk
about what's bothering you
or would you like to break
some more furniture?
Today on the promenade,
a Yridian approached me.
He knew who I was and...
tried to sell me
information about Mogh.
Your father?
He claimed that he's alive
and is being held captive
in a Romulan prison camp.
Oh, my God.
Could it be true?
A Klingon would never
allow himself to be captured.
A warrior fights
to the death.
If my father were alive,
it would dishonor his sons
and their sons
for three generations.
Even Alexander would bear
the burden of guilt.
So you're willing
to ignore the possibility
because you're concerned
about dishonor?
My father is dead.
That Yridian
is selling lies.
If you're so sure about that,
why are you still so upset?
Worf, you can't deny
the possibility
just because you don't
want it to be true.
If you want to talk about this,
you know where to find me.
If we transfer
20 megajoules of energy
from the dilithium chamber
into the plasma inputs
it should be sufficient
to activate the device.
Hmm, it's worth a try.
You two can begin by connecting
the coil to the chamber.
I'll configure
the energy transfer.
Right.
Data, can I ask you
a personal question?
Certainly.
Does your hair grow?
I can control the rate of
my follicle replenishment.
However, I have not
yet had a reason
to modify
the length of my hair.
Why do you ask?
Oh, just curious.
Power conduits
are ready.
Is something wrong,
Doctor?
Well, you're breathing.
Yes.
I do have a functional
respiratory system.
However, its purpose
is to maintain
thermal control of
my internal systems.
I am, in fact,
capable of functioning
for extended periods
in a vacuum.
And you have a pulse.
Mmm.
My circulatory system not only
produces biochemical lubricants,
it regulates
micro-hydraulic power.
Most people are interested in
my extraordinary abilities--
how fast I can compute,
my memory capacity
how long I will live.
No one has ever asked me
if my hair will grow
or noticed that
I can breathe.
Well, your creator went
to a lot of trouble
to make you seem human.
I find that fascinating.
Okay, I think we're ready
to begin the transfer.
Power connections
are complete.
I'll monitor
the coil's transfer rate.
Will you keep an eye on
the transient power response?
Of course.
We are ready, Geordi.
Okay.
Initiating energy transfer.
Power levels
are holding steady.
Transient response
is normal.
Hold on.
I'm picking up a power surge.
Reduce the transfer rate.
Reducing rate by 20%.
LA FORGE:
What happened?
BASHIR:
The power connections blew.
It sent out some kind
of plasma shock.
LA FORGE: His synaptic energy
is dropping...
( distant metallic banging )
( banging continues )
Data, are you
all right?
I believe so.
What has happened?
A plasma shock overloaded
your positronic net.
You were down
a good 30 seconds.
That cannot be possible.
I have a memory record
for that period of time.
I can recall
a series of images.
I saw Dr. Soong...
my father.
( sighs )
Data, I can't find
anything wrong
with your positronic
subprocessors or your
circuit controllers.
No sign of any residual
energy fluctuation.
Cascade overload...
My internal diagnostic indicates
that my memory systems
are functioning
within normal parameters.
For the 47 seconds
I was inactive,
there is no record
of cognitive activity.
Well, there's no doubt
about it, Data,
you were completely
shut down.
Maybe you had
some kind of...
random power fluctuation.
Caused you to access
one of your memory files.
That cannot be.
The image I saw was of
Dr. Soong as a young man.
I did not encounter him
until much later in his life.
There appears to be no rational
explanation for my experience.
Well, I'll take another
look at the diagnostic log.
In the meantime,
we'd better
disconnect that device.
Hmm.
Data...
perhaps we're going
about this the wrong way.
How so?
Well, maybe you had a dream
or a hallucination.
I am not capable of either
of those functions.
Yet, you can't account for
what happened today, can you?
At present, I cannot.
Well, maybe you should
approach this from a more
human standpoint.
You're right that machines
can't have hallucinations,
but then again,
most machines can't grow hair.
Wait.
What is it,
Commander?
I am sorry
to bother you,
but I have a question
of a personal nature.
Do you have a moment?
A moment.
I have heard you mention that
you once experienced a vision.
Yes, when I was young,
my adoptive parents
arranged for me
to partake in
the Rite of MajQa.
I understand it involves
deep meditation
in the lava caves
of No'Mat--
that prolonged exposure
to the heat
induces
a hallucinatory effect.
Why are you asking me
about this?
I have recently had
an unusual experience
which might be described
as a vision.
Well, what happened?
An accident in Engineering
shut down my cognitive functions
for a short period of time
yet... I seemed to
remain conscious.
I saw my father.
You are very fortunate.
That is a powerful vision.
If it was a vision,
I do not know how to proceed.
You must find
its meaning.
If it has anything
to do with your father,
you must learn
all you can about it.
In the Klingon
MajQa ritual,
there is nothing
more important
than receiving a revelation
about your father.
Your father is
a part of you...
always.
Learning about him
teaches you about yourself.
That is why,
no matter...
where he is
or what he has done...
you must find him.
But I am not looking
for my father.
Yes, of-of course.
Do not stop until
you have the answer.
Thank you, Worf.
Ah...
Lieutenant Worf.
You have reconsidered.
Yes, I wish to go to
the Romulan prison camp.
Excellent.
I can provide you
with the coordinates.
No. You will take me there.
No. It's not possible.
I have no means
of transportation.
I checked
the station records.
You have a vessel that is
capable of warp speed.
I... I do not have the time.
I have other business.
What is the real reason
you do not wish to take me?
Is it because what you
have told me is not true?
No, the camp is located
on the edge of Romulan space.
It is a dangerous journey.
Dangerous?
It would be more dangerous
for you to refuse.
Oh. Very well...
but I will require
full payment in advance.
No, no.
I will pay you after.
But...
( grunting )
Yes, yes.
Of course, after.
If you are lying,
if there is no prison camp...
No.
...I will kill you.
Oh... oh...
( panting )
The Romulan guards have
a detection perimeter.
It will be necessary to
transport you to the surface,
30 kilometers
from the prison camp.
WORF:
The foliage is very dense.
It will take me approximately
12 hours to reach the camp.
I may have to travel
during the night.
That would be unwise.
This is not
an empty jungle.
There are many predators.
I am prepared.
Very well,
but I recommend
that you look up
from time to time.
The arboreal needle snake
likes to attack from above.
( laughing )
I will provide you
with a map of the camp.
How did you learn
of this camp?
It is not important
for you to know.
Why have you not informed
the Klingon government
of this place?
I sell information.
I do not give it away.
Ah, you do this for profit.
I have my reasons...
Mr. Worf.
What reasons could you have
for letting these people suffer?
We will arrive
in the Carraya sector
in approximately
three hours.
I suggest
you get some rest.
( door chimes )
Come.
Yes, Mr. Data?
I am sorry
to disturb you, sir.
Ah, not at all.
I'm here studying
the intricacies
of Bajoran
aqueduct management.
I would welcome
a little interruption.
Please sit down.
I require
your advice, sir.
I have come to an impasse
regarding my recent
unexplained experience.
Hmm, your vision
of Dr. Soong.
How is your
investigation proceeding?
I have analyzed over
4,000 different religious
and philosophical systems,
as well as over 200
psychological schools of thought
in an effort to
understand what happened.
And what have you found?
I have been unable to find
a single interpretation
of the images I saw during
the time I was shut down.
The hammer, for instance,
has several meanings.
The Klingon culture views
the hammer as a symbol of power.
However, the Taqua Tribe
of Nagor sees it as an icon
of hearth and home.
The Ferengis view it
as a sign of sexual prowess.
I am curious,
Mr. Data.
Why are you looking at
all these other cultures?
The interpretation
of visions and other
metaphysical experiences
are almost always
culturally derived,
and I have no culture
of my own.
Yes, you do.
You're a culture of one,
which is no less valid than
a culture of one billion.
Perhaps the key
to understanding
your experience
is to stop looking into
other sources for meaning.
When we look at Michelangelo's
David or Symnay's Tomb,
we don't ask, "What does this
mean to other people?"
The real question is,
"What does it mean to us?"
Explore this image,
Data.
Let it...
excite your imagination.
Focus on it.
See where it leads you.
Let it inspire you.
I believe I understand, sir.
Thank you.
Good luck, Mr. Data.
( faint rustling )
The camp is in
a southeasterly direction.
After approximately
ten kilometers,
you will come to the edge
of the sulfur canyon.
Look for a riverbank
and follow it
until you come to
the camp.
This is a homing device.
It will allow you to find
my ship when I return.
I will not be landing in
the same location.
When will you return?
50 hours.
Do not be late.
( distant animal cries )
( splashing )
( splashing continues )
( twig cracking )
Who's there?
Toq... is that you?
I can see you.
I hope you're
enjoying yourself.
Toq, I swear,
I will hang you by your...
( gasps )
Stop!
Please.
Who are you?
I have come to help you.
Help me?
Yes.
How did you get out of camp?
Does anyone know you are gone?
Yes.
I come here often.
You must lead me
to the camp.
You are Klingon.
Where did you come from?
That does not matter.
I have come
to take you home.
Home?
This is my home.
( footsteps )
MALE:
Ba'el?
It is very important
you tell no one you saw me.
Have they begun
the ceremony?
Yes.
They're about to begin.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Data, what are you doing?
We were supposed to meet at...
I am painting.
I can see that.
How long have you
been at this?
I have created
23 individual illustrations
in the past six hours,
27 minutes.
I believe you could say...
I have been inspired.
I'll say.
I have done
as Captain Picard suggested.
I have tried to
explore the images.
Has it helped?
I am not certain.
I began by painting
the image of
the blacksmith.
Hmm.
Then I painted
the corridor.
After that...
the anvil,
the hammer...
and Dr. Soong's face.
The thought
then occurred to me...
that I should paint smoke.
LA FORGE:
Smoke? Why smoke?
DATA:
I cannot explain it.
It is not an image
I saw during my vision.
Well, you have the smoke
coming out of a bucket of water.
Blacksmiths used to use
water to cool the metal.
Maybe that's why
you painted it.
Perhaps.
After I painted the smoke,
it then occurred to me...
to paint a bird's wing.
I then drew
an entire bird,
a flock of birds
flying in formation,
an individual feather.
If the image of the bird
is related to my vision,
I do not understand how.
I am left with more
of a mystery than ever.
Geordi, I would
like to re-create
the experiment which caused
my initial shutdown.
What for?
I do not know
how much longer
my vision would have continued
had I not been reactivated.
Data, that plasma shock
almost fused your neural net.
I don't think it's such
a good idea to try that again.
I am aware of
the risks involved,
but I can think of no other way
to investigate my experience.
Will you help?
( sighs )
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
I'll go find Dr. Bashir.
I will prepare
the power transfer.
Okay, Data,
we're going to monitor
every subsystem
in your positronic net.
If I see any neural pathways
overload beyond 65%,
I'm shutting down
the experiment.
Agreed.
We're ready.
Initiating
energy transfer.
Get ready, Data.
( humming )
Power levels are rising.
( humming intensifies )
Should be any second now.
( metallic banging )
( banging grows louder )
( hissing )
( cawing )
The bird did not appear
in my original experience.
This vision is different.
DR. SOONG:
Of course it's different.
It's never the same.
Always changing...
unpredictable.
( laughs )
It doesn't make sense.
( wings flapping )
What is happening, Father?
I don't know, Data.
What is happening?
We are on the deck
of the Enterprise.
My cat is present...
my potted plant...
and my paintings.
A beginning.
Still a little grounded
in the mundane, but...
showing promise.
I do not understand.
You're not supposed to.
No man should know where
his dreams come from.
It spoils the mystery...
the fun.
I'm proud of you, son.
I wasn't sure
you'd ever develop
the cognitive abilities
to make it this far.
But if you're here--
if you can see me--
you've crossed over
the threshold
from being
a collection
of circuits
and subprocessors
and have started
a wonderful journey.
What type of journey?
Think of it...
think of it as an empty sky.
I do not understand.
Shh.
Just dream, Data.
Dream.
Data...
you are the bird.
( hammering )
DATA: The images I saw during
the time I was shut down
were generated by a series
of previously dormant circuits
in my neural net.
I believe Dr. Soong
incorporated those circuits
into my base programming,
intending to activate them
once I had reached a certain
level of development.
But the plasma shock
activated them prematurely.
That is correct.
I'm curious.
Now that those
circuits are active,
what are you going
to do with them?
I plan to shut down
my cognitive functions
for a brief period
each day.
I hope to generate
new internal visions.
It sounds to me like you're
talking about dreaming.
An accurate analogy.
Remarkable.
You know, this is
just the kind of thing
that might get me published
in the Starfleet Cybernetics
Journal.
Would you mind if I authored
a paper on all this?
Of course not.
Thank you, Data.
And... sweet dreams.
Hmm.
( indistinct conversation )
( male singing in Klingon )
♪ ...teblaw'nghu ♪
♪ Mughato'Du ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo' ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo'... ♪
( indistinct voices )
♪ ...van'aj javDich ♪
♪ Qong Dir sa'vich ♪
♪ Ghih yot ♪
♪ Queli'pa Qevas ♪
♪ Hoh Qa ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo' ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo'. ♪
( murmuring voices )
( muffled cry )
Quiet!
I'm a friend.
Who...
who are you?
Worf.
Son of Mogh.
Why have you come here?
I've come to find
my father.
Is he alive?
Is he here?
Your father fell
at Khitomer.
Did he... die in battle?
He was fortunate.
You were captured?
Yes.
The Romulans--
they robbed you of
your right to die in battle.
There is very little time.
How many Klingons
are being held here?
Seventy-three.
How many Romulans
guard the camp?
Worf, there are things
you do not understand.
What do you mean?
I must... I must speak
with the elders.
( grunts )
Ghos!
I knew your father
well, Worf.
And I remember you--
a boy...
barely able to lift
a bat'leth.
Once, your father insisted
we take you on the ritual hunt.
You were so eager,
you tried to take the beast
with your bare hands.
It mauled your arm.
I still have the scar.
I do remember you now.
You should not
have come here, Worf.
I do not understand.
You should not have come.
Who is this?
I'm Worf, son of Mogh.
I have come
to help you escape.
He does not know.
He must leave at once.
No, it is too late
for that now.
He would bring others.
Vang ghaH!
( grunting and groaning )
We are not leaving here
and neither are you.