Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
Not all the Klingons
at Khitomer
were killed
during the massacre.
Many were captured
by the Romulans
and placed in a prison camp
on a remote planet.
Your father was among them.
If my father were alive,
it would dishonor his sons
and their sons
for three generations.
Even Alexander would bear
the burden of guilt.
So you're willing
to ignore the possibility
because you're concerned
about dishonor?
My father is dead.
That Yridian
is selling lies.
This is a homing device.
It will allow you to find
my ship when I return.
You are Klingon.
Where did you come from?
That does not matter.
I have come
to take you home.
He must leave at once.
No, it is too late for that now.
He would bring others.
Vang ghaH!
We are not
leaving here
and neither
are you.
And now, the conclusion.
Take his pack.
Are you afraid to die
while escaping?
We are dead, Worf.
We died at Khitomer.
We were captured.
It was worse than death.
Well, why did you
allow it to happen?
We had no choice.
We were defending an outpost
on the perimeter.
The Romulans
took out our shields.
The next blast
rendered us unconscious.
And when we awoke,
we were prisoners,
unarmed and shackled.
We were interrogated
for three months.
We tried to
starve ourselves,
but they
kept us alive.
The Romulan Commander, Tokath,
thought he was being kind.
The Romulans
hoped to trade our lives
for territorial concessions,
but the Klingon High Council
refused to negotiate.
They would not acknowledge
that their warriors
had been taken prisoner.
And when it was clear that
we would be of no use to them,
Tokath offered
to let us go.
But we knew that
our families believed
we had fallen in battle,
so we did not wish
to return to dishonor them.
We asked Tokath to let us stay
and he took pity on us.
I understand your desire
to preserve
your family's honor.
But what of your own?
There is no honor
in remaining prisoners.
We lost our honor
when we were captured.
It does not matter
what happens to us.
All that matters
is that our families
are not dishonored.
Why did you
come here, Worf?
If you had
found your father,
you would have found
only dishonor.
If he had been captured,
as you were--
if I had
found him here--
I would be glad
to see him.
There is no room
in my heart for shame.
I can only hope
that if my son came here,
he would be Klingon enough
to kill me.
PICARD:
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( quiet conversations )
This is a gin'tak spear.
What of it?
Have your parents
taught you nothing?
This is used for battle,
not tilling soil.
We have no need
for weapons here.
The war is far away.
What war?
The war our parents
came here to escape.
That war was over
many years ago.
I'm not interested in what
you have to say, Klingon.
I've got work to do.
Hello again, Worf.
They say you've come
to stay with us.
Not by choice.
Well, aren't you happy
to have escaped the war?
The war.
Yes.
We've heard the stories
all our lives.
How people are slaughtered
in terrible battles--
forced to fight whether
they want to or not.
And that's why our
parents came here--
to make a safe home
a place where they could
raise their children in peace.
I should think
you'd be relieved
to get away from the fighting,
you're safe here.
A place can be safe
and still be a prison.
Where I come from,
people are free to
come and go as they choose.
So are we.
Tell your father that you
would like to leave.
Tell him that you
would like to visit
the Klingon homeworld.
See what he says.
Why would I want to go there?
It's dangerous.
Not any longer.
WOMAN:
Ba'el. Come here.
Yes, Mother.
You are not allowed
to leave the compound?
Then I suppose I won't be
seeing you at the pond again.
I told you not to
speak with him.
I'm sorry, Mother.
( faint beeping )
( beeping stops )
( sighs softly )
( knocking at door )
Enter.
I am Tokath.
I can return later
if I'm disturbing you.
It is a strange thing when
the jailer concerns himself
with his
prisoner's comfort.
Mine is a strange prison.
You robbed the Klingons
of who they were.
You dishonored them.
By not slitting their throats
when we found them unconscious?
I do not expect you
to understand.
You are a Romulan.
( sighs )
You're just like
L'Kor was 20 years ago--
proud and angry.
He hated me.
All the Klingons did.
And I had
no love for them.
I won't deny it.
When I informed
the High Command
that the Klingons
wanted to remain here,
I was told
that unless I stayed
to oversee them myself,
they would be killed.
My decision ended
my military career.
Why did you do it?
I don't expect you
to understand.
You're a Klingon.
But I do expect you
to understand this.
We've put aside
the old hatreds.
Here, Romulans and Klingons
live in peace.
I won't allow you
to destroy what we have.
Do not deceive yourself.
These people
are not happy here.
I see the sadness
in their eyes.
That's not what I see
when I look in my wife's eyes.
I married a Klingon.
So you see, when I warn you
not to disrupt our lives here,
I'm not speaking
just as a jailer,
but as a man
protecting his family.
Do not test
my tolerance.
( singing softly )
♪ Bagh Da tuH moh ♪
♪ ChojaH Duh rHo ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo' ♪
Do you know
what that song means?
No.
I just like the melody.
Stop!
There.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46759.2:
The Yridian vessel Lieutenant
Worf boarded at Deep Space Nine
has failed to arrive
for our scheduled rendezvous.
It is now 12 hours overdue.
Still no sign of them
on long-range scanners.
Contact DS9.
Find out what they know
about this Yridian trader.
Hopefully, he filed
a flight plan before
he left the station.
It's the only chance
we have of finding Worf.
We haven't had to
use one of these
for a long time.
It implants a small
boridium pellet
underneath the skin.
We can use its energy
signature to track you.
In time, you will grow
accustomed to life here.
Never.
He is one of yours,
deal with him
however you like.
But I warn you,
if he becomes a disruption,
I will not be
so tolerant.
Toq.
You guard him.
He is free to move around
inside the compound,
but make certain
he does not cause trouble.
What are you doing?
This is the mok'bara.
The form clears the mind...
and centers the body.
No. Like this.
First, you must learn
how to breathe.
Stand tall,
as tall as you can.
Now, take a wider stance.
You must stop.
These forms are the basis
for Klingon combat.
You would be wise
to learn them.
I will teach you.
Join us.
We'll see what L'Kor
thinks of this.
Mother?
She's not here.
Come in.
This is what
I wanted to show you.
I don't know why,
but I'm not supposed
to look at these things.
They're Klingon,
aren't they?
Yes.
I thought you might be able
to tell me about them.
This is
a warrior's armor.
And this is a d'k tahg.
It should not be allowed
to rust like this.
Isn't it beautiful?
That is a jinaq.
It is given to a daughter
who has come of age...
old enough
to take a mate.
Ba'el!
Mother...
Put that away at once.
Why is she forbidden
to know what these things are?
They are not needed here.
Go!
Kahless held his father's
lifeless body in his arms.
He could not believe
what his brother had done.
Then, his brother threw their
father's sword into the sea,
saying if he
could not possess it,
neither would Kahless.
That was the last time
the brothers would speak.
What happened to the sword?
Kahless looked
into the sea
and wept,
for the sword was all
he had left of his father.
The ocean filled
with his tears
and flooded
over the shore.
That is impossible.
For you, perhaps.
Not Kahless.
He was a great warrior.
You're making it up.
No.
These are our stories.
They tell us who we are.
It is late.
It is time to sleep.
BA'EL:
Worf.
You never answered
my question.
Did Kahless ever find
his father's sword?
Yes.
He found it.
The stories that you tell...
are they true?
I have studied them
all of my life
and find new truths
in them every time.
This Kahless...
did he ever...
take a mate?
That is another story.
Tell me.
You are Romulan.
Tokath is my father.
I thought you knew that.
How could your mother
mate with a Romulan?
Why shouldn't she?
It is an obscenity.
What are you saying?
They love each other.
Romulans
are treacherous.
Deceitful.
They are without honor.
My father
is a good man.
He is kind and generous.
There is nothing
dishonorable about him.
He took part in a cowardly
attack at Khitomer.
Thousands of Klingons
were massacred,
many of them women
and children.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
My father came here
to escape the wars.
He would never kill anybody.
Ask him.
Ask your mother.
Tell them you want
to know the truth.
What is it,
Number One?
We just received
the Yridian's flight plan
from Deep Space Nine.
He gets around.
He's been to three different
systems in this past week.
He could have left Worf
at any one of them.
Are any of these systems
near Romulan space?
Two of them--
the Nequencia
and the Carraya systems.
Let's head
for the closer one.
Aye, sir.
( knocking )
What do you want?
I am...
sorry if I upset you.
I was surprised.
I became angry.
But I do not
blame you.
You cannot help
being what you are.
There is nothing wrong
with what I am.
What I mean is...
it is not your fault.
What, being born?
I'm sorry if that
offends you.
No.
It is hard to explain.
Klingons and Romulans
are blood enemies.
Have been for centuries.
Not here.
Here we live in peace.
But I don't live here.
Worf...
before you knew,
you were attracted to me.
Can't you leave
the hatred behind, too?
Can't you accept me
as I am?
I, I do not know.
It's set.
Come on.
MAN:
Come on, Toq.
Hey!
WOMAN:
Nice.
MAN:
Very good.
Who's next?
MAN #2:
It's Toq again.
MAN:
Toq again?
MAN #2:
Uh-huh.
Here, Toq.
MAN #2:
Okay?
Let's see.
MAN:
Try again, Toq.
WOMAN:
Pick it up!
Ka'la!
That is not how you play
this game.
The Qa'Vak is not a game.
It hones the skills
of the hunt.
The "hunt"?
We have replicators here.
Klingons do not hunt
because they need food.
The hunt is a ritual
that reminds us
of where we come from.
I know where I came from--
right here.
It is a difficult skill
to master.
Perhaps you are too young.
Your arm is strong.
But you need practice.
Hold your other arm
like this
and aim along it.
Roll.
Ka'la!
You learn quickly.
Perhaps it is time
to put your skills
to the test.
What do you mean?
Come.
I will take you
on the hunt.
You are not allowed
to leave the compound.
They won't allow it.
I think they will.
Hunting?
Have you lost your mind?
The boy can
come with me.
I cannot sit in the compound
like an old man.
I must practice
my skills.
We can't let you out.
You've already tried
to escape once.
I give you my word
as a warrior--
I will not try to escape.
Leave us.
We have work to do.
Tokath.
He gave his word.
Are you seriously suggesting
that we open the gates
and let him wander free
with only a boy
as his guard?
23 years ago,
I gave you my word.
In all this time,
have I ever broken it?
I told you he was yours
to deal with.
If you want
to take this risk,
the responsibility
is yours.
You will go with him.
Take a weapon.
If he breaks his word
and tries to escape...
kill him.
He is there.
The wind has shifted.
We must wait.
Why?
We're so close.
Never approach
your prey from upwind.
The breeze will
carry your scent.
The wind is
shifting again.
I can't smell anything.
He is there.
How can you...?
Yes.
I can smell it.
Remember the scent.
More than anything else,
it will guide you.
Oh, it is strong!
I cannot believe
I couldn't smell it before.
Let it work its way
into your blood.
I can feel
my heart pounding.
Yes.
This is the moment
where life and death meet.
This is what we are...
warriors.
I was never taught that.
There is much
you were never taught.
( rustling )
Aren't you hungry, L'Kor?
Or are you upset because
your prisoner has not returned?
I should not have sent
the boy with him.
If he has
been hurt, I...
Don't worry,
my friend.
They'll come back.
After all,
a warrior keeps his word.
Isn't that so?
Father, if I wanted
to visit Romulus
or the Klingon homeworld,
would I be allowed to go?
( footsteps approaching )
Ka'la!
( angry muttering )
Tonight, we eat well.
Get that off my table.
You do not kill an animal
unless you intend to eat it.
Get rid of it.
I intend to, Tokath.
But not until it's cooked.
( men laughing )
Today, I learned
the ritual hunt.
But that is not
all I learned.
I discovered that
warrior's blood
runs through my veins.
I do not know
how or why,
but we have
forgotten ourselves.
Our stories
are not told.
Our songs are not sung.
Tonight, as we came home,
we sang a song of victory--
a song known only to me
as a lullaby.
But it is
a warrior's song.
Bagh Da tuH moh.
Fire streaks the heavens.
ChojaH Duh rHo.
Battle has begun.
♪ Bagh Da tuH moh ♪
♪ ChojaH Duh rHo ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo' ♪
♪ MajoQ'oDu ♪
♪ Jih Dok maju' ♪
♪ Pah ok chabah ♪
♪ BuraQ chuQo ♪
♪ Teblaw'nghu ♪
♪ Mughato'Du ♪
♪ Ylja'Qo ♪
Ba'el.
♪ Ylja'Qo... ♪
♪ Van'aj javDich... ♪
Well, Worf, you've had quite
an effect on the young people.
I have done nothing more
than show them who they are.
No, you have shown them
what you want them to be.
Tell me this.
Do you know of any place,
any time in history
when Klingons and Romulans
have lived together in peace?
We have despised each other,
fought each other
for centuries,
except here.
On this remote planet,
Romulans and Klingons
live together in harmony.
No government...
no leader has ever done
what I have done here.
And what about Toq?
I saw what
happened to him
when he caught the scent
of his prey on the wind.
For the first time in his
life, he felt powerful,
and that is what he has
been denied living here.
And that is what you have
tried to take away from him.
Now, you may be
content to sit here
in the jungle
and wither to old age,
but Toq and the others
have tasted what it is
to feel truly alive
and they will not
give that up now.
Enough of this.
We could talk all night
and not convince each other.
I offer you a choice--
live with us
as one of us...
Or...?
Or I will have you...
put to death.
Then that is what
you will have to do.
Worf, consider
this carefully.
That death
will be honorable.
The young people will see
what it is to die...
as a Klingon.
( knocking at door )
Enter.
Thank you.
I will remove
the tracking device.
Then you can go over the wall
and hide in the jungle.
Why are you doing this?
My father is wrong.
No matter how I might feel about
you, you don't deserve to die.
I am not going
to run away, Ba'el.
They will kill you.
Yes, but they
will not defeat me.
I don't understand you.
A Klingon does not run
away from his battles.
Is that really the lesson
you want us to learn?
You've taught us
a great deal,
awakened something inside us
that we never knew existed,
but I don't understand what
we can learn from your death.
Then you do not yet understand
what it is to be Klingon.
Worf...
in spite of everything
that's happened,
I still sense that...
that you care for me.
Am I wrong?
You talk so much
about being a warrior,
about honor and death.
Is it so hard
to speak of love?
Worf, please.
I would not have
thought it possible
to love a Romulan.
But you do.
Yes.
Well, if you've
come that far,
can't you take it
one more step?
Can't you stay here with us?
With me?
If there were a way,
I would take you
away with me.
If there is anything
that I've learned from you--
from your reaction
to me--
it's that I have
no place out there.
Other Klingons
will not accept me
for what I am.
And if I stay here,
these Klingons will not
accept me for what I am.
Why did you come here?
We were so happy.
We didn't know that there was
anything missing in our lives.
Ba'el...
Good-bye, Worf.
( door closes )
( murmur of conversation )
I know that there
are those among you
who may question
what I am about to do,
and you would not
be wrong to do so.
I have questioned myself.
I have spent the night
considering my decision--
challenging myself to
justify whether it is right
and I have reached
the conclusion
that it is
absolutely necessary...
to put this man to death.
What we have
built together
would be destroyed
by this man
and I cannot allow
that to happen.
I give you one last chance
to accept our way of life.
Those are eloquent words,
Tokath,
but the truth is,
I am being executed
because I brought
something dangerous
to your young people--
knowledge.
Knowledge of their origins,
knowledge of the real reasons
you are here in this camp.
The truth is
a threat to you.
Enough.
Stand ready.
Raise your weapons.
Father...
TOQ: Stop this!
If you kill him,
you will have to kill me.
Step aside, Toq.
Worf would rather die
than accept this way of life
and so would I.
I want to leave,
as do many others.
You will have to kill us
to keep us here.
You see, Tokath...
it is already
too late.
I'm warning you.
Move aside now.
Stand ready.
Toq... move away.
Take aim...
Ba'el.
Tokath.
Long ago,
when your captives
asked to stay here,
our hope was to avoid
dishonoring our children
on the homeworld,
but perhaps
over the years,
we lost sight of
our children
that we raised here.
This is our prison.
( sighs )
It should not
be theirs.
Years ago, your parents
made a great sacrifice
for the sake
of their families.
Today,
they do so again.
For that,
we must honor them.
You must promise them
never to reveal
their secret.
No one must know
of this place.
A supply ship is due
in a few days.
They will take us.
When they arrive,
Tokath will explain it to them.
Then we will start
a new life.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
Our search for Lieutenant Worf
was cut short
when we received
a cryptic message from him
requesting a rendezvous
with a Romulan vessel.
He has informed us we will
be taking on passengers.
It's good to see you.
He seems fine.
We're giving everyone
a thorough checkup in Sick Bay.
Thank you, Doctor.
Welcome home,
Mr. Worf.
Thank you, sir.
Picard to Bridge.
Signal the Romulan ship that
the last group is on board.
BRIDGE: Aye, sir.
You found what you were
looking for, Mr. Worf?
No, sir.
There was no prison camp.
Those young people are
survivors of a vessel
that crashed in the Carraya
system four years ago.
No one survived Khitomer.
I understand.