Captain's Log,
Stardate 46682.4.
The Enterprise is docked
at the Remmler Array,
where it will undergo
a routine procedure
to eliminate accumulated
baryon particles.
In preparation for the sweep,
we are evacuating the ship.
Attention, personnel
on decks 14 and 15.
Your transporter room
assignment has been changed.
Report
to transporter room three.
Captain, we're still
behind schedule on
decks seven and eight.
Shall I tell Arkaria Base
there'll be a delay?
No. Open up the transporters
on Cargo Bay Two
and divert everyone
from deck seven to there.
That should put us
back on track.
Right.
All beta shift
engineering personnel
are requested to report
to main engineering...
Captain, the Arkaria Base
does not have
the medical storage units
I requested.
I have seven
living tissue samples
that won't survive
the baryon sweep
any more than
you and I would.
I've tried to
reason with them.
All right, uh, have
Commander La Forge
transport a stasis unit
from the astrophysics lab.
You should be able
to convert it to
store tissue samples.
Thank you, Captain.
All science personnel,
please check in with
your section chief
for a station-side
duty assignment.
Captain. I'm heading
to deck seven.
I've put the auto-shutdown
sequence on hold
until we get back
on schedule.
Oh, I think we can
resume the sequence.
Counselor Troi is
taking care of the
situation on deck seven.
Aye, sir.
Captain.
Bridge.
It has been quite
a day, has it not?
Yes, it has.
However, a change
of routine is often
invigorating
and can be a welcome
diversion after
a long assignment.
Exactly.
I understand that Arkaria
has some very interesting
weather patterns.
Mr. Data,
are you all right?
Yes, sir.
I am attempting to fill
a silent moment with
nonrelevant conversation.
Ah. Small talk.
Yes, sir.
I have found that humans
often use "small talk"
during awkward moments.
Therefore, I have
written a new subroutine
for that purpose.
How did I do?
Perhaps it was a little...
too nonrelevant,
but if you really are
interested in small talk,
then you should keep your
eye on Commander Hutchinson
at the reception
this afternoon.
He's a master.
Hmm. Thank you,
sir. I will.
LA FORGE:
Captain.
WORF:
( both talking )
After you, sir.
No, after you.
No, sir. I believe
you spoke first.
Gentlemen, gentlemen,
we're running of time.
Mr. Worf?
The computer needs
your authorization
to disable command functions
during the baryon sweep.
Are we ready,
Commander La Forge?
Almost. I've requested two
additional field diverters,
one for the computer core,
one for the bridge.
They haven't been
installed yet.
Additional units?
Yes, sir. We've logged,
in five years,
more warp hours than
most ships do in ten,
so our baryon particle
levels are high.
I'm a little concerned
that when the Remmler Array
starts to sweep the ship,
it'll have to use
a stronger beam than normal
in order to get rid
of all the radiation.
And that might overload
the field converters
protecting our key systems.
How long until the
new ones are in place?
I'd say about 20 minutes.
Very well.
Computer, disable
all command functions
in 30 minutes.
Authorization: Picard
gamma-six-zero-seven-three.
Authorization
acknowledged.
Captain.
Incoming message.
It's the station
administrator, Mr. Orton.
In my ready room,
Mr. Worf.
And, Captain, request
permission to be excused
from Commander Hutchinson's
reception.
Permission granted.
I wish I could
excuse myself as well.
Captain, permission...
Mr. La Forge,
I cannot excuse
my entire senior staff.
Mr. Worf beat you to it.
Go ahead, Mr. Orton.
Captain, if you're
on schedule, I'd
like to confirm
that we'll begin
the baryon sweep
at 1500 hours--
approximately
one hour from now.
Confirmed.
Commander Hutchinson
also wanted me to make sure
that you'll be able to attend
his reception this afternoon.
Tell him I'm
looking forward to it.
He'll be delighted
to hear that.
Arkaria base out.
( sighs )
Tell Arkaria Base we're
almost finished here.
MAN:
We're going to need
two more conduits.
WOMAN:
I need to run a diagnostic
on the diverter.
Get the diverter aligned
so we can begin
the isolation procedure.
Where's the ODN
interface?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( soft music playing )
RIKER:
Your Remmler Array
is considered...
MAN 1:
Here you are.
MAN 2:
That's nice to hear.
RIKER:
What are these?
MAN 2:
Briskian cheese pastries.
TROI:
Geordi, would you get me
some more fruit salad?
Beverly, lovely as ever.
How do you manage it?
It's good
to see you again.
It's been far too long.
What is it, four years?
Now, I want to hear
about everything
that happened after you
left Starfleet medical.
And I have so much
to tell you.
Oh, that must be
Commander Riker.
Excuse me.
Of course.
Pardon me.
You must be Will Riker.
I must be.
Calvin Hutchinson.
Call me Hutch.
Calvin-- awful name.
I've never forgiven
my parents.
Soon as I saw you,
I knew you had to be
the Enterprise's
first officer.
Oh?
Oh, of course.
Your reputation
precedes you--
flashing blue eyes,
square jaw--
quite the ladies' man,
I hear.
Now, don't be
modest, Will.
Oh, may I
call you "Will"?
Uh, sure.
I also hear that
you're a musician.
I certainly hope you'll
play something for us.
It's not often
we get to entertain
the command crew
of the flagship.
Oh, and speaking
of command.
Hello, Captain Picard.
Commander.
I was just telling
your first officer
what a real pleasure
it is to have
all of you here.
So how are you, anyway?
Very well.
Thank you.
What have
you been up to?
It is very good
to see you both again.
Beverly...
may I call
you "Beverly"?
Beverly, have you noticed
that the mean temperature
here on Arkaria
is slightly higher
than normal for
human comfort levels?
I have found that humans
prefer a body temperature
of 21 degrees Celsius
in order to operate
most efficiently.
However, there are
several cultures
who actually prefer that
their body temperature
is identical to the
temperature of the room
in which they are standing.
( chuckling )
The Sheliak,
for example...
I am telling you,
you have never seen
anything like this.
There were thousands
of these creatures.
The whole northern sky
turned dark.
Oh, uh, Geordi...
Deanna.
I don't think you
have met our host.
This is Lieutenant
Commander Geordi La Forge.
Hello.
Hi.
Counselor Deanna Troi.
This is
Commander Hutchinson.
Oh, please,
call me Hutch.
Hello.
I was just telling
your captain here
about some of the more
fascinating sights
here in Arkaria.
Either of you interested
in ornithology?
Uh, well...
The mating habits
of the Arkarian horn fowl
are quite interesting.
If the weather were better,
we could take horses
to the southern
promontory and visit
the nesting grounds.
Horses?
Yes.
We have a network of trails
through the plains.
Unfortunately, it's not
very pleasant right now--
cold, muddy.
Not a soul
for kilometers.
Sounds perfect.
Mr. La Forge, how long
before the baryon sweep
begins on the Enterprise?
About 25 minutes, sir.
Then I have enough time
to go back to the ship
and get my saddle.
TROI:
Your saddle?
Yes. A saddle is
a very personal thing.
It has to be, uh,
broken in, used, cared for.
You keep a saddle
onboard the Enterprise?
Oh, yes, yes.
I never know
when I will have
the opportunity to ride.
I see.
It's perfectly normal.
You know, most
serious riders do have
their own saddles.
Of course.
Absolutely.
Well, if you
will excuse me.
Amazing man.
You know, he reminds me
of another officer
I knew years ago--
a Captain Edwell.
Now, he was fascinating.
Born on Gaspar VII,
but you wouldn't know it
from the way he looked.
COMPUTER:
Auto-shutdown sequence
in progress.
Defensive systems
off-line.
Baryon sweep begins
in eight minutes.
MAN:
What are you doing?
Someone left this ODN
junction box open.
I thought your crew
was supposed to be
off the ship
once the field diverters
were in place.
The diverters
have to be synchronized.
I was laser bonding
a backup link.
I see.
Well, I better
let you finish up
so that you
can get off the ship.
Excuse me a minute.
Auto-shutdown sequence
in progress.
Primary power off-line
in one minute.
WOMAN:
We still need to bypass
the magnetic
containment conduit.
MAN:
That should be down
on deck 30.
Well, then get Pomet
started on it right away.
Primary power off-line
in 30 seconds.
Final warning.
Primary power off-line
in ten seconds.
Hmm... yes.
I find it fascinating
that your family chose
to drop the prefix "Pel"
from your surname.
It was my understanding
that "Pel Orton"
is a more noble appellation
than simply "Orton."
Yes.
Hmm.
Perhaps the recent
Arkarian trend toward
a more egalitarian society
is partly responsible, huh?
Perhaps.
The crew of the Magellan
actually put on
a talent show here.
Captain Conklin
did a poetry reading,
if you can imagine that.
I'm trying to.
Did I ever tell you
how I happened
to be stationed here?
It's a fascinating story.
I was serving on
Admiral Mitchell's staff
on Starbase 97--
awful place, by the way.
Have you met
our Commander Data?
Hmm?
...as a matter of fact,
I find it oddly amusing.
( laughs loudly )
No, I don't think so.
Come on,
I'll introduce you.
DATA:
There are several
cultures in this sector
with extremely similar
etymological histories.
For example...
Mr. Data, I don't know
if you've had a chance meet
our host,
Commander Hutchinson.
"Call me Hutch."
Lieutenant Commander Data,
our second officer.
A pleasure.
The pleasure
is mine... Hutch.
I've been meaning
to compliment you
on your choice
of colors here.
Oh, you really
think so, hmm?
Well, it wasn't easy
making a final decision,
let me tell you.
I can well imagine.
The light in this room
would make color selection
exceptionally problematic.
Precisely.
( both laughing )
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm not sure which one
to feel sorry for.
Mr. Orton?
You'll excuse me,
Commander?
Geordi, what happened
to the captain?
Oh, he went back
to the ship to
get his saddle.
His saddle?
Any serious rider
would have his own saddle.
Oh.
He probably went
straight to the stables.
I bet he's ten kilometers
from here already.
Lucky him.
Thank you.
Kelsey to Devor.
Devor, this is Kelsey.
Reply.
Devor, do you read me?
Kelsey to Kiros.
This is Kiros.
KELSEY:
Devor isn't responding.
There must be
too much interference
from the baryon sweep.
Go find him and see
if he finished
bypassing the regulator
on deck seven.
Then meet us
in main engineering.
Understood.
Hey.
Who are you?
What are you doing
on my ship?
The baryon sweep
uses a high-frequency
plasma field.
Your phaser won't work.
You're probably
right, but I'd like
to bet this will.
A laser welder
can be deadly.
Now, what's going on
in main engineering?
I suggest
that you cooperate.
You're Starfleet.
You won't kill me.
You sure?
( hissing )
( groans )
It seems you're right.
( laughter )
Yes, but
Tyrellian laser-art
is very similar in both
form and composition.
Well, of course.
You know, funny you
should mention that.
I used to be stationed
on Tyrellia.
Really?
Yes.
Did you know there are
currently
five Tyrellians serving
aboard the Enterprise?
That's fascinating.
Not too many people
know this, but Tyrellia
is only one of three
known inhabited planets
without a magnetic pole.
I was aware of that,
but are you aware
that Tyrellia is one
of seven known planets
with no atmosphere
whatsoever?
Really?
Mm.
They're still at it.
Nonstop.
I have to admit,
it has a sort of
strange fascination.
How long can two people
talk about nothing?
Is something wrong?
Uh, I don't know.
I was just getting some
very strange energy readings
from your table here.
Well, I'm sure
it's nothing serious.
Perhaps the heating
element underneath the
table is malfunctioning.
Maybe I should take
a look at it for you.
I'm sure we can
handle this,
whatever
it is, Commander.
There's no need
to concern yourself.
LA FORGE:
Well, maybe I should
look at the element.
I mean, in case...
It's all right.
Please, don't worry.
What's that all about?
ORTON:
I assure you, Commander
La Forge, it's all right.
We'll look into it.
You don't have
to concern yourself.
Orton, now!
( grunts )
What is going on?!
( groans, Troi gasps )
Stay right where you are.
Reduce the plasma pressure
to 0.6 percent nominal.
Zero point six.
How does
the conduit look?
It's clear.
All right.
The main plasma flow
has been shunted to
the aft conduit.
We're ready here.
Okay, that should
do it, I think.
Be sure, Neil.
Uh, yes.
Yeah, that does it.
Um, all right.
Transfer 500 milligrams
from the reserve system
to the engine core.
Perfect.
Adequate. Disable
the containment overrides
and get the interlocks
off the magnetic seal.
Pomet, prepare
the transport assembly.
Keep watching
that power flow.
It might...
Keep working.
Where'd he come from?
Found him on deck seven.
Who are you?
My name is Mot.
I'm, uh,
I'm the barber.
Barber? What the hell
are you doing here?
Everyone was supposed
to be evacuated
to the surface.
Yes, I know, um...
but I wanted to go riding,
but I didn't have my saddle.
So, I went back...
Your saddle?
Yes, that's right.
It's on deck seven.
I left it in
the corridor.
And then the power went out,
and I got lost, and...
All right, all right,
shut up.
I didn't know...
Just shut up!
Any sign of Devor?
No.
( sighs )
Satler.
Get down here,
and, uh...
keep an eye
on our barber.
All right, go see if
you can find Devor.
Make sure
nothing's wrong.
Sit down.
All right.
Look, just don't point
that thing at me.
Just do what I
tell you, and you
won't have to worry.
How long
until you're ready?
40, maybe 50 minutes.
The baryon sweep
hits this compartment
in 30 minutes.
The field diverter
will protect us.
It is not us
I'm worried about--
it's that storage unit.
I want the trilithium
resin in there and secured
before the sweep gets here.
I don't want to take
any chances.
Understood.
( sighs )
They haven't tried
to communicate
with the outside.
No demands, no
political statements...
no theft.
They must want something.
Orton is not as calm
as he looks.
He's very agitated
and nervous,
as if something's
gone wrong.
It is possible
that Geordi upset
their timetable
when he saw the
hidden weapons.
Orton may be
improvising.
Maybe he didn't plan to
take us hostage so early
and now he doesn't
know what to do.
If they do not
have a plan for
this contingency,
we may have
the initiative.
Maybe, but we need to
figure out how to use it.
How is he?
There's no
permanent damage.
I've adjusted the
optical transducer
in his visor
to block out
some of the pain
receptors in his brain.
It's only
partially effective.
I need to get him
to a medical facility.
I doubt if they'll
agree to that.
But maybe if we tell
them Geordi's dying,
they would give us access
to a medical kit.
We might be able to
use some of the tools
to make a weapon.
Perhaps we can use
the visor as a weapon.
If the optical transducer
were modified,
we might be able
to generate
a hypersonic pulse.
A hypersonic pulse
would overload
the audio receptors
of everyone in this room.
It would cause
immediate unconsciousness.
Can you make the adjustment
on the visor yourself?
It will look suspicious
if you're both working on it.
CRUSHER:
I'll try.
I might need Geordi
to help me through
some of it.
RIKER:
All right.
Be as casual
as you can.
Let me know when
you're ready.
Ready.
All right, begin
draining the trilithium
at 100 milligrams
per minute.
( alarm wailing )
Neil, what's going on?!
Neil, get over here!
Put that down!
Protect it.
NEIL:
Don't worry, I've got it.
I'll be right there.
( Satler screaming )
The primary inducer
is completely fused.
There's no way to fix it.
Without the diverter,
we don't have any protection
from the baryon sweep.
I know that.
How long before the
baryon sweep gets here?
About 12 minutes.
We should go
to Ten-Forward.
That's the last place
on the ship
that'll be swept
by the baryon field.
All right.
We're leaving.
But we're taking
the trilithium with us.
What?!
Do you know how
volatile trilithium is?
We can't just start hauling
it through the ship.
I'll... I'll try to
make some modifications.
Satler's dead.
He ran into
the baryon sweep.
What about Mot?
I don't know, but I
don't think he's a barber.
I found this
in the Jefferies tube.
( communicator beeps )
Kelsey to Kiros.
This is Kiros.
We have a problem.
There's a Starfleet
officer still aboard.
He's killed Satler
and he may have
killed Devor.
He also destroyed the
diverter in engineering,
so we have to leave here
before the baryon sweep
enters this section.
What about
the trilithium resin?
We're taking it with us
to Ten-Forward.
There should be
enough time before...
Kelsey, don't be a fool.
You know better than to try
to move trilithium resin.
Mr. Mot, or should I
call you "Lieutenant"?
"Lieutenant Commander,"
perhaps?
You can call me
whatever you wish,
but moving trilithium
resin requires very
specific equipment.
You can't just
improvise something.
I wouldn't need
to improvise
if you hadn't damaged
our field diverter.
But if you're so concerned
about the trilithium,
I suggest you stop
interfering with us before
you set off an explosion
that would destroy
the Enterprise and you.
I would rather
destroy the ship
than allow that resin
to fall into the hands
of terrorists.
What makes you think
I'm a terrorist?
Trilithium resin is a
highly toxic waste product
produced by our engines.
It's only possible use
could be as a weapon.
You might be right,
Mr. Mot,
but we've been planning
for this for a long time,
and I doubt you'll really
be able to stop us...
( no audio )
...or even slow us down.
There.
300 milligrams
of trilithium.
I'm, uh, using
a dynamic stabilizer
to act as a control rod.
There.
That should keep
the resin stable
enough for transport.
Come on!
( gasps )
Don't be so tense, Neil.
Listen, if something
goes wrong,
you won't have time
to worry about it.
Let's go.
Three more decks.
Then we take
corridor 15-B all
the way to Ten-Forward.
What's wrong?
We have to find
another way up.
The rungs are cut.
KELSEY:
That wasn't very
clever, Mr. Mot.
If you knew where
we were, you should
have attacked us.
Now we'll just take
another route--
one you might not
be able to predict.
There are only so many
ways to Ten-Forward.
Ten-forward is the
logical place to be
if you want to stay ahead
of the baryon sweep.
That sweep is just
as big a threat to you
as it is to us.
In fact, if I
were you, Mr. Mot,
I'd be trying to find
another way off this ship.
I plan on leaving
the same way you do--
on your ship.
What ship?
Come on, Kelsey.
If you've been
planning this so long,
you must have a way
of getting off
the Enterprise and
leaving this system.
I think you have
a ship coming for you.
I plan to be on it.
It's a small ship, Mot.
I don't think there's
going to be room
for both of us.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I'll send your regrets.
How is he, Doctor?
He's in a lot of
pain, but I think
he should be fine.
He needs some water.
Is that all right?
( speaking softly ):
We're almost ready.
When we set the
visor to emit the
hypersonic pulse,
there'll be a
short burst of light.
We need a distraction.
They need a distraction.
How long?
Just a few seconds.
I think I can distract
Orton for a few seconds.
I don't think Orton's
in a talking mood, Will.
You just have to know
how to talk to him.
Orton, I think we need
to discuss this situation.
There is nothing
to discuss.
Sit down.
There is a lot
to discuss.
Can't we be reasonable?
I am not interested
in hearing
your hostage negotiation
tactics, Commander.
Well, it can't hurt you
to listen, can it?
All right.
Thank you.
Now, the first thing
I think we need to
discuss is this.
( grunts )
( grunts in pain )
KIROS:
Hold it.
Put your weapon down.
Kelsey, this is Kiros.
I'm on deck ten.
I have Mot.
Is he alive?
Yes.
Good. Meet us
at intersection 41.
Understood.
This way.
( panting )
Give me the trilithium.
How much farther
do we have to go?
Not far.
With all the modifications
you've made to this unit,
are we going to have
any problems removing
the trilithium?
No. Just remove
the control rod.
Drain the unit.
There shouldn't
be any problem.
That's all
I wanted to know.
Well, not as clever
as you thought.
Where's Pomet?
He shot him with
some kind of an arrow.
He's not dead.
Well, he will be soon.
The sweep's nearly here,
and we don't have time
to go back for him.
What about Neil?
The sweep got him.
Let's go.
I thought you were just
going to talk to him.
I did. He just didn't
like what I had to say.
( beeping )
Mm.
That was a perimeter
warning from the
Remmler Array.
A small ship
is approaching.
I believe Mr. Orton
has dropped his
defense shields.
This must be the sign
they were waiting for.
Mr. Data, you will be
the only one unaffected
by the hypersonic burst.
As soon as everyone
else is unconscious,
I need you to get to
that computer panel and
stop that ship somehow.
I will try, sir.
Now.
( high-pitched humming )
Kelsey, perhaps we
can work out a deal.
You're the only one
who needs a deal, Mot.
My name isn't Mot.
It's Jean-Luc Picard.
Captain Picard.
This is all beginning
to make sense.
Leave the trilithium here
and take me with you.
You can use me as
a hostage instead
of threatening...
I am not a
terrorist, Captain,
nor do I have
a political agenda,
although I know
some people who
do have agendas,
and they are very
interested in this
little container.
Profit. This is
all about profit.
I prefer to think
of it as commerce.
Open the door.
Now go through...
slowly.
( yelling )
( both grunting )
( beeping )
Well, Picard, I guess
I'll be the one to
send your regrets.
Picard to Arkaria Base.
Deactivate
the baryon sweep.
Arkaria Base,
this is Captain Picard
onboard the Enterprise.
Deactivate
the baryon sweep.
Arkaria Base,
this is Captain Picard.
Deactivate the baryon
sweep immediately!
Data to Captain Picard.
Do you read me, sir?
Picard here.
Are you all right,
Captain?
Yes, Mr. Data.
Sir, an unidentified
scout ship
has just beamed someone
off the Enterprise.
Do you know
anything about it?
I know they won't
get very far.
Hold still.
You have a nasty
little cut here.
Any luck?
I'm sorry, Captain.
I don't know what could
have happened to it.
Hold still. I can't
heal this cleanly
if you don't
stop fidgeting.
I've had three security
teams search deck seven.
They couldn't find
anything.
There.
I found it.
Someone put it in
a maintenance locker.
Thank you.
Captain, you keep
a saddle on board?
RIKER:
Mr. Worf, I'm
surprised at you.
Anyone who is
an experienced rider
naturally has
his own saddle.
TROI:
It's perfectly normal.
Actually,
it came in handy.
I only wish I had
had the opportunity
to use it on a horse.
Of course.