Good evening, Mr. Data.
Actually,
good morning, sir.
Ship status is--
No need to report.
I'm just here to do
some work on my own.
Aye, sir.
I'd like to speak
to Professor Mowray
at his archaeological
site on Landris II.
Could you put it through
to my ready room?
I am sorry, sir, but stellar
cartography has requested
a communications blackout
while they run an experiment.
Hmm. How long
will it be?
Another three hours,
22 minutes, sir.
I can override,
if necessary.
No, it's not important.
Aye, sir.
Computer,
display the latest
excavation schematics
on Landris II.
Library computer
is temporarily off-line.
Explain.
Library systems
have been allocated
to stellar cartography.
( sighs )
Tea, Earl Grey.
Hot.
COMPUTER:
Replicator systems
are off-line
at the request of...
BOTH:
stellar cartography.
What could they possibly
be doing down there?
Oh...
In or out-- just
close that door.
And don't move.
It'll take a second
for our eyes to readjust.
Okay.
Elevate to 3.2, Marquez.
MARQUEZ:
Now at 3.2, Commander.
Good. Good.
We can do this.
No, no, no. We're losing
vertical alignment.
Compensate. Compensate!
Compensating.
Gently. Gently, Marquez.
Don't bump it.
( buzzing )
No! No, no, hit the--
Oh... oh, forget it.
Forget it.
Lights.
Whoever you are,
you just ruined
four hours of work.
You might have taken
the simple precaution
of locking the door.
It's 3:00
in the morning...
Captain Picard.
I assume that you must be
Lieutenant Commander Daren.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry. It's just we
weren't expecting anybody
to be up at this hour.
Well, you're new
on the Enterprise.
You'll have to learn
to expect the unexpected.
That's why I put in for
this assignment, sir.
Excellent. Now, perhaps
you can tell me
what was so important
that it required
depriving the captain
of his cup of Earl Grey.
Earl Grey? No wonder
you can't sleep.
Computer, bring replicators
back online
and give me a cup
of Daren herbal tea
blend number three,
hot.
You shouldn't be
drinking a stimulant
at this time of night.
I think
you'll like this.
I-- I've programmed
seven other blends
into the replicator.
You're bound to
like one of them.
I look forward
to sampling them.
( coughing )
( chuckling )
I'm sorry if, uh,
the system blackouts
we requested...
inconvenienced you.
We're taking very precise
gravimetric readings,
so it wouldn't have taken
much to throw them off.
What were
the readings for?
Well, I'm trying to construct
a mathematical model
of an emerging
star system.
If it works, we'll
be able to predict
the configuration
of a star system
that won't be formed for
another two million years.
A long time to wait
to see if you're right.
I have a few things to do
between now and then.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
Captain, we'll be arriving
at the Borgolis Nebula
in three hours.
Yes, I understand
that it has some unusual
radioactive emissions.
Well, I'm sure that
stellar sciences
will find it a most
interesting study.
Commander Daren has already
requested extra time
on the main
sensor array.
Well, you have the
bridge, Number One.
Captain?
I would like
to remind you
of our concert this
evening in Ten Forward.
We will perform Chopin's
"Trio in G Minor."
I'll be there.
PICARD:
And so, the upshot is,
that we'll be close enough
for you to slip away
for a few days
and see Wesley.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Thank you, Jean-Luc.
This is delicious.
What is it?
Mmm, it's
a herbal tea blend.
I, um... found it
in the replicator files.
Oh.
Have you met any
of the new crew members
who came aboard
at Starbase 218?
In fact, I have
a new nurse-- Beck.
He's an obstetrics
specialist.
I met the new head
of stellar sciences last night--
Lieutenant Commander Daren.
Yes...
Nella Daren.
She came into sick bay
for a physical last week.
I like her--
very forthright.
Did you know...
that it is now possible
to predict the configuration
of a star system
which won't be formed
for another two million years?
Really?
No, I didn't.
Mm-hmm. It's really
quite intriguing.
The whole thing
is made possible
by a complex
mathematical construct
based on fractal
particle motion.
But that's only
the foundation.
The modeling itself is done
by gravimetric wave input.
I see.
Hmm.
Well...
I know this is all
pretty dry stuff.
Stellar cartography
isn't everybody's cup of tea.
I'm sure it's really
quite fascinating.
You know, we should be
getting along to Ten Forward.
We're going to be late
for the concert.
( audience murmuring )
( door opens, closes )
( playing Chopin's
"Trio in G Minor" )
Thank you.
DAREN: Thank you.
Will you
excuse me?
Yes,
of course.
Well done, Mr. Data.
Well done.
Commander, that was
a remarkable performance.
You are very talented.
Thank you.
I noticed that the
applause this evening
exceeded average
decibel levels.
I guess that means
they enjoyed themselves.
I think that much
was obvious.
Excuse me.
I have not yet
congratulated
Ensign Cheney.
I'll go with you.
Commander, you must have been
playing since you were young.
I played the piano
for a while when I was small,
but I didn't put in
the practice you must have.
Well, practicing was
never my problem.
In fact, my parents had to
make me go out and play.
I wanted to ask,
uh...
during the second arpeggio
of the first movement,
I noticed that you played
an F minor chord
instead of a diminished D.
You're a musician.
What's your instrument?
We should play sometime.
No, no, no.
I'm-I'm just an amateur.
But your choice in that
arpeggio was delightful.
Not at all
what one would expect.
Well, Captain,
now that I'm on your ship,
maybe you should start
expecting the unexpected.
Ah.
Excuse me, sir.
I was hoping that my people
in spectral analysis
could have another few hours
on the main sensor array?
I'm sorry.
The array has already
been allocated
to engineering.
They're running
some warp field tests.
If we go off-line
now, we'll lose
the gas flow pattern
we've been tracking.
I understand, but there are
other departments
waiting to use the array.
We're at a critical
juncture, sir.
( firmly )
Commander...
( sighs )
I'll see what I can do
to find you
some more time
tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, sir.
( flute playing Bach's
"Third Brandenburg Concerto" )
( door chimes )
Computer, pause playback.
Come.
Oh... Commander Daren.
I hope you don't mind me
dropping by like this?
No. Please, come in.
I'm delighted.
What kind of
a flute is that?
It's, uh...
Ressikan.
I've never
seen one before.
They're not made
any more.
have you been playing long?
Um...
yes, a long time.
I'd love to hear you
play sometime.
I'm not very good.
Well, that doesn't matter,
as long as you enjoy it.
Yes, but I wouldn't
want to inflict it
on someone else.
May I try?
Yes, of course.
Hmm, now...
Yes, you're-- you're not
holding it quite right.
May I?
Please.
( playing slow melody )
You're-- You're better
than you think.
Really!
We should play together.
Uh... there
isn't a piano.
Ah, but there is.
I picked it up
on Mataline II.
It's amazing.
( plays ascending arpeggio )
That is remarkable.
Well, why don't you
play something?
You start,
and I'll jump in.
What should we play?
What were you working on
before I came in?
Um, Bach,
the "Third Brandenburg."
perfect.
Go ahead.
( sighs, clears throat )
( plays opening melody )
Uh... I'm sorry.
Oh. It's all right.
You're not used to playing
with anyone, are you?
Just the computer.
Hmm.
Well, I may not be
as precise as a computer,
but... well, I think
you'll enjoy it more.
Uh, why don't we start
with something
a little simpler.
How about...
( slowly playing
"Frere Jacques" )
( both playing "Frere Jacques"
in round form )
Good!
Very good.
Now, let's have
a little fun with it.
( playing improvised version
of "Frere Jacques" )
Go on, you try it.
Improvise around
the melody--
anything
you want.
( playing improvised version
of "Frere Jacques" )
Good.
That's wonderful.
Keep going.
( both playing improvised
versions of "Frere Jacques" )
( chuckles )
It's so good.
( piano coda plays )
You're definitely better
than you think.
( sighs )
Number One,
my fencing partner's
canceled for
this afternoon.
I was wondering if you
wanted to join me.
Fencing?
Mm-hmm.
I'm not really
very good.
Ah, it doesn't matter
so long as you...
ch-ch-ch-ch...
( clicking )
Enjoy it.
Why not?
Good! Excellent.
1400 hours, then.
You have a mild strain.
Oh.
I've been playing
the piano a lot.
I guess the captain and I
overdid it a little last night.
The captain?
Yes, he plays
a kind of flute...
um, a Ressikan,
I think he said.
Yes, but I didn't know
he played duets.
Well, he never
did before.
He seemed
to enjoy it.
He's actually
quite promising.
I see.
Tell me, have you
known him long?
Yes, a very long time.
He seems...
somewhat isolated.
I'd say he's
a very private person,
but not isolated.
There,
that should help.
Hmm, that feels
much better.
Thank you.
Good.
I was afraid
I might have to cancel.
Another duet?
Keep climbing.
Where are we going?
We're almost there.
I don't see why we couldn't
just practice in my quarters.
( sighs )
Do you know
where we are?
Uh, yes. This is
the fourth intersect
in Jefferies tube 25.
No... this is the most
acoustically perfect spot
on the ship.
( playing "Moonlight Sonata" )
The intersection acts
as a resonance chamber.
How did you find it?
A little exploring.
You mean to say
that you crawled through
every tube on the ship?
Well, not every one.
Try it.
See how it sounds.
( Picard playing melody
from "Inner Light" )
That's beautiful.
What is it?
It's, um...
an old folk melody.
I've never heard you play
with such feeling.
( picking out notes
of "Inner Light" melody )
( Daren adding chords
to song )
( Picard picks up melody
on flute )
( distant music playing )
( music stops )
is there a problem,
Geordi?
I hear music.
Music?
I do not hear anything.
You sure?
Mm.
I know I heard
something.
Hmm...
it stopped.
Hmm.
I'd heard about Kerelian
tenors all my life,
but nothing could
have prepared me
for this man's
voice.
Soaring,
incredible range.
Hmm.
Wonderful.
I understand
that there are nuances
that only Kerelians
can pick up.
We just don't have
the ears for it.
Mmm.
I should be
finished with
my survey
by 1100 hours.
( brusquely )
Very good, Commander.
Captain, the Federation
outpost on Bersallis III
reports that they are
entering a period
of firestorm activity.
Bersallin firestorms happen
on a seven-year cycle.
They're not expecting any
for another eight months.
We don't rendezvous
with the Havana
for another two days.
That would give us
plenty of opportunity
to study this
phenomenon.
Helm, set a course
for Bersallis III,
warp five.
Aye, sir.
Counselor, could I speak
with you in my ready room?
You have the bridge,
Number One.
Sit down, Counselor.
I wanted to talk to you
about a matter of protocol.
I know there are
no Starfleet regulations
about a captain
becoming involved
with a fellow officer.
But--
You would like my opinion
about you and
Commander Daren?
It's that obvious?
In a way
that pleases people
who care about your happiness,
yes, it is.
But I have to
be concerned
about more
than my own happiness.
And you think that
your feelings toward Nella
could change the way
you function as captain?
Yes.
Relationships
with coworkers
can be fraught
with consequences.
That's true,
but cutting yourself off
from your feelings
can carry consequences
that are just
as serious.
You see, I've
always believed
that becoming involved with
someone under my command
would compromise
my objectivity.
And yet...
Captain, are you asking
my permission?
If I were,
would you give it?
Yes.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Nella?
Can I help you,
sir?
( sighs )
I'm really very sorry
about what happened
in the turbolift.
When the crew member
walked in,
I felt very
self-conscious.
It's going to take
a while
for me to get used
to the idea
of crew seeing
the two of us together.
I understand.
Now, I'm glad you told me.
For a minute there,
I thought
I'd misread you.
One kiss, and you're off
to find somebody else.
I can assure you that I'm not
given to casual relationships.
There is something
that I want to tell you...
but not here.
Do you remember
the folk melody that
I played to you this morning?
Yes. Yeah.
I learned it on a planet
called Kataan.
Never heard of it.
No, I'm not surprised.
Its sun went nova more than
a thousand years ago.
I don't understand.
The Enterprise
encountered a probe
that had been sent
from the planet
before it was destroyed.
And it scanned me,
and I lost consciousness.
And...
in the space
of 25 minutes,
I lived a lifetime
on that planet.
I had a wife and...
and children
and a grandchild.
And it was
absolutely real to me.
And when I awoke,
all that I had left
of that life
was the flute that
I'd taught myself to play.
Why are you
telling me this?
Because I want you
to understand
what my music
means to me...
( sighs )
...and what it
means for me
to be able to
share it with someone.
Thank you.
Hello.
Sir.
Commander, I was
hoping to talk to you
about Ensign Cabot's
transfer.
Quantum mechanics doesn't
want to give him up.
But he wants to come
to my department.
How do you know that?
I offered it to him.
Transfers are to
be approved by me
before any offers
are made.
I'm sorry.
We were just talking,
and...
It's all right, but Cabot
should stay where he is.
Commander, please don't make
that decision final.
I realize I shouldn't
have made the offer,
but he's perfect
for the job,
and quantum mechanics
is overstaffed, anyway.
Commander, do you realize the
position you're putting me in?
Well, I-I think
I'm just doing
what any good
department head would do--
trying to build
the best staff I can.
Look, I'll review
the situation.
I'll let you know
as soon as I can.
( door chimes )
Come.
May I have a minute?
Yes, of course.
Come in, Number One.
It's about Lieutenant
Commander Daren.
As a department head,
she comes to me
for systems allocation,
personnel transfers,
things like that.
Well...
I'm beginning to feel
uncomfortable
with her requests.
Because of her
relationship with me?
Yes, sir.
Are her requests unusual?
No.
Would you say that she's
just trying to do her job?
Yes, sir.
Then let her do it, and you
feel free to do yours.
Ship's resources are
your responsibility.
I have always had absolute
confidence in your judgment.
Thank you, sir.
( sighs )
I can't believe I'm going
to get the chance to study
the firestorms
on Bersallis.
Apparently,
they're generated
by particle emissions
from the Bersallin sun.
They cause a cascade effect
in the planet's atmosphere
that...
Oh, I'm boring you.
No. No. No, you're not.
Not at all.
( sighs )
It's just that...
Commander Riker
came to see me this afternoon...
about you.
About the personnel
transfer.
I thought
he looked uncomfortable.
He thought I was asking
for special treatment.
I was just doing what I thought
was best for my department.
And that's what I told him.
But...
we have to be careful.
Obviously, it's easy
for people to misunderstand.
I don't like the thought
of having to second-guess
people all the time.
If I have to worry about what
people are thinking about me,
I'll be concentrating
on the wrong thing
and I won't be
as effective an officer.
All I'm saying is
that it's something
we have to be aware of,
but you mustn't
compromise yourself.
You must do
what you have to do,
because if I find that
my head of stellar sciences
isn't being effective,
then I shall do what I must do--
and I shall replace her.
Noted, sir.
Now, I think that we should
just forget about this
and enjoy our evening.
What about that special
dessert you promised me?
Right. Now, this is something
that I first tasted
on Thelka IV...
WORF:
Bridge to Captain.
Go ahead, Mr. Worf.
WORF:
Bersallis III reports
that the storm has changed
its speed and heading.
They are predicting
it will hit the outpost
within eight hours
and are requesting evacuation.
I'm on my way.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46693.1:
We have entered
the Bersallis star system
and are making
preparations to evacuate
the Federation outpost
on the third planet.
A firestorm can
kick up winds
of over 200
kilometers per hour
and temperatures
as high as 300 degrees C.
Incredible.
What causes them?
They form when
solar flare radiation
reacts with
high-energy plasma
present in
the planet's atmosphere.
Wasn't the outpost constructed
to withstand the conditions?
It was-- both reinforced
and insulated.
But this is
no ordinary storm.
It's twice as strong
as anything they've ever seen.
The outpost just
won't withstand it.
We'll arrive about an hour
before the storm gets there,
and it'll take us
at least two hours
to evacuate the colonists
off the surface.
I led a team of geologists
to study the plasma geyser
on Melnos IV.
Now, we cross-connected
a few thermal deflector units
to create a protective shield
against the heat.
A firewall.
Mm-hmm. Would something
like that work here?
You know... it might.
The storm is approaching the
outpost from this direction.
If we were to set up a series
of thermal deflector units
along the northern perimeter,
we could create a firewall
and deflect
some of the heat.
The insulation
from the outpost
should be able
to handle the rest.
Thermal deflectors
generate a field
approximately
400 meters wide.
We would need to
cross-connect six units
and align them so that
the fields overlap.
How many people would
it take to set that up?
Twelve-- two per team.
Cross-connecting that many
units, it'll be a little tricky.
Once they're set up, we'll have
to leave the units in place
and transport our people out.
Nobody would be able
to survive
very long outside
that structure.
Let's do it.
The storm is going to
interfere with communication.
Everything will need to be
coordinated from the surface.
Mr. Data, you will coordinate
the evacuation of the colonists.
Doctor, there are nine patients
in the outpost infirmary.
Your first priority will be
to get them to Sick Bay.
After that, you will stay
on board the Enterprise.
Be ready to receive
casualties.
Marquez, you'll take some people
down and track the storm.
All the other teams will need to
be kept apprised of its heading.
Commander, you'll be in charge
of deploying the deflectors.
Let's go.
Commander Daren?
About those
thermal deflectors.
There must be one
of any number of people
that coordinate
their deployment.
I assume Commander
Riker chose me
because I'm the best
person for the job.
Didn't we agree not
to let our relationship
get in the way
of our work?
I'll be all right.
Lieutenant Marquez is already
set up on the surface.
Apparently, the storm
is gaining speed.
He's estimating
it'll hit the colony
in less than
50 minutes.
Ensign, make sure you maintain
a continuous transporter lock
on all away team
personnel.
We may have to pull
them out in a hurry.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
RIKER: I don't want to take any
unnecessary chances down there.
If anyone gets into trouble
beam them up immediately.
Energize.
Mr. Worf, how long until
the storm reaches the outpost?
17 minutes.
La Forge to Bridge.
Go ahead, Mr. La forge.
The ionization from
the storm is interfering
with the transporters,
Captain.
I'm compensating, but it's
slowing things down a bit.
PICARD:
Keep at it, Mr. La Forge.
RIKER:
Riker to Daren.
Daren here.
Go ahead, Commander.
RIKER: You've got less than
nine minutes before the storm
reaches
the northern perimeter.
I'm here with team six.
We're just about to bring
the deflectors online.
RIKER:
Whenever you're ready.
Daren to perimeter teams.
Stand by to
cross-connect deflectors.
MAN: Standing by.
Activate.
Team three, increase your
output by point two percent.
WOMAN: Yes, sir.
Good, good.
Deng, decrease nutation
by point four percent.
Good.
We've almost got it.
Crusher to Bridge.
Go ahead, Doctor.
We just brought back the last
of the infirmary patients
and they're on
their way to Sick Bay,
but we still have over
100 colonists down there.
Understood.
Daren to Commander Riker.
Riker here. Go ahead.
DAREN:
We've got a problem.
We're having trouble keeping
the deflectors cross-connected.
So, the only way
this is going to work
is if we calibrate
them manually.
RIKER:
If you stay with the deflectors,
will they protect you
when the storm hits?
DAREN:
I don't know, sir.
A few minutes maybe.
( static hissing )
Picard to Commander Riker.
How many more colonists
do you have to transport?
73, sir.
How long do you need?
At least ten more minutes.
Captain,
the storm will reach
the northern perimeter
in four minutes.
Picard to perimeter teams.
It is imperative
that you hold your position
until we've finished
evacuating the colony.
Picard out.
Picard to Mr. La Forge.
La Forge here.
I want a signal lock
on every member
of the perimeter teams.
LA FORGE: Captain, the storm's
interference won't...
As soon as the last
of the colony is evacuated,
I want those
perimeter teams out of there.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
( electrical zapping )
( wind howling )
Daren to perimeter teams.
The storm's interference
is going to make our job
harder than we thought.
We may lose communication,
so it's up to each of you to
keep your units operational.
A lot of people
are depending on us.
Daren out.
Oh, my God.
( wind roaring )
The storm has reached
the perimeter.
( murmuring voices )
I got out with
the last of the colonists.
If it hadn't been
for the perimeter teams,
none of us would
have made it.
We were able to clear
out four of the teams
and the interference prevented
us from getting two more.
I don't know how
they could have survived.
Which teams are missing?
Three and six.
The last I knew,
Commander Daren
was on team six.
WORF:
Bridge to Captain.
Go ahead, Mr. Worf.
WORF:
We have found survivors, sir.
They are beaming up now.
I'm on my way.
( indistinct voices )
( whoosh of
active transport )
That's it.
Here, let me help you.
Thank you.
Here, just give
me your hands.
You're going to be fine.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46697.2:
Although we succeeded
in rescuing
all 643 Bersallin colonists,
we lost eight crew members.
Let the record show
that they gave their lives
in the performance
of their duty.
When communications
went out,
I knew we had to fend
for ourselves.
We modified our phasers
to create resonant disruptions
in the deflector field.
The disruptions
formed small pockets
in the plane
of the field
and we each stood inside one
to wait out the storm.
Richardson
didn't make it.
All Deng and I could do
was stand there...
and watch.
I'm so sorry.
Don't, don't say
you're sorry.
It must have been terrible.
At first, when you told us
to hold our positions,
I didn't question it.
Of course we would.
That was our job.
But when I saw that storm
coming toward us...
A part of you
must have blamed me.
A small part, maybe.
But, in the end,
I was more afraid
that you'd blame yourself
if I died.
Would you have?
I've lost people
under my command...
people who were
very dear to me...
but never...
someone I've been
in love with.
And when I believed
that you were dead,
I just began to shut down.
I didn't want
to think or feel.
I was here in my quarters...
and the only thing I could
focus on was my music
and how it would never again
give me any joy.
And then I saw you standing
on the transporter pad.
And I knew that I could
never again put
your life in jeopardy.
If I stayed here...
you might have to.
You could always resign
your commission.
Stay here with me.
And you could
resign yours
and come to
a starbase with me.
( chuckles )
I'll apply...
for a transfer.
But we could
still see each other.
People do.
We could arrange
shore leave together.
And, for the future...
who knows?
Of course.
Promise me something.
Don't give up your music.