Captain's Log,
Stardate 46731.5.
We're in the midst of
the Volterra Nebula--
a stellar nursery.
Our three-week mission
is a routine analysis
of several dozen protostars
in various stages
of development.
Captain, I have completed
the spectral evaluation
of the outer shell.
Our survey of this protostar
is complete.
Ensign, lay in a course for
the next one, 3/4 impulse.
Riker to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Number One.
RIKER: May I see you in the
observation lounge, sir?
I'll be right there.
Oh, my God.
MAN: Then you can identify
that object, Mr. Picard?
Professor Galen?
Computer, lights up.
I suppose I should say,
"Captain" Picard.
The professor contacted me
from his shuttle
about an hour ago.
He suggested that
we surprise you.
To clarify, I insisted,
and your first officer
was good enough
to accommodate me.
I trust I'm not being
overly presumptuous,
now that my star pupil
is master of the stars?
No one could be more
welcome on the Enterprise.
I never thought I would
see a Kurlan naiskos.
Fifth Dynasty?
Is that your conclusion,
Mr. Picard?
Forgive me again.
I should say Captain.
Oh, please.
Mister will do fine.
Um... well...
the overall impression is
certainly Fifth Dynasty.
Um... the...
the surface ornamentation...
Yes?
Green polychrome over the eyes
and the eyes themselves
are closed.
( snaps fingers )
This is Third Dynasty.
From the workshop of
the Master of Tarquin Hill.
Well done.
Will...
the Master of Tarquin Hill
designed ceramic objects
that were 300 years
ahead of their time.
All we know of him
is the work.
His name was never discovered.
This object is over
12,000 years old.
The planet Kurl?
That's a hell of a long way
outside Federation territory.
Indeed-- I thought your
study of Kurlan artifacts
was done long ago.
Well, I happened to be in
the neighborhood last summer.
I couldn't resist.
Go ahead.
You mean, it's complete?
Oh...
( sighs )
Will.
The Kurlan
civilization believed
that an individual was a
community of individuals.
Inside us are...
many voices,
each with its...
its own desires,
its own style,
its-- its own
view of the world.
The Kurlan
civilization died out
thousands of years ago.
It is extraordinarily rare
to find a figurine intact.
Professor, this is
an incredible find.
It's yours, Jean-Luc.
Oh, no.
No.
How can I accept this?
Graciously,
Mr. Picard.
You could accept it
graciously.
Thank you.
( sighs )
How long can you stay?
There's so much
to talk about.
The professor is scheduled
to meet a Vulcan transport
the day after tomorrow.
Two days? But that's
not enough time.
We may have considerably
more than that.
I don't understand.
I am currently
on an expedition--
a journey into an unexplored
and historical territory--
and I intend
to take you with me.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
It's been over 30 years
since I last saw
my archaeology professor.
His presence has taken me
back to a time
when I had considered
a very different career.
May I ask you a
frank question?
Please.
Your published writings
have been sporadic
for the past decade.
Your appearance at
symposia has been rare
or scheduled and
then canceled
at the last moment.
The finest archaeologist
of this century is now...
shrouded with a
cloak of mystery.
And as a result,
my reputation
has no doubt grown.
( chuckles )
I've never heard of anyone
who didn't love
a good mystery.
The Satarran of Sothis III
disdain them,
but as a general idea,
your statement holds.
So, what have you been
doing for the past decade?
Are you familiar with
micropaleontology?
Yes, it's the study
of fossil records
at the microscopic level.
I read your papers
on the subject, but...
that was years ago.
It seemed as though
the work had stopped.
No.
The work continued.
I made a discovery
so profound in its implications,
that silence seemed
the wisest course.
This work has occupied
my every waking thought.
It's intruded
upon my dreams.
It's become my life.
When finished...
and I announce my findings,
it'll be heard halfway
across the galaxy.
Tell me.
I cannot, Mr. Picard.
That information
comes with a price--
your agreement to join me
on the final leg
of this expedition.
For how long?
Three months.
Perhaps a year.
If I had complete diplomatic
access and a starship,
it'd be a matter of weeks.
But, as it is,
we'll only have my shuttle
and whatever arrangement we
can make with transports...
combined with our talents.
Why do you need
my help in this?
I am not a young man.
There will be hazards
along the way.
I don't want my
own inadequacies
to jeopardize
the completion of this work.
I'm deeply honored
that you should
think of me, but...
( sighs )
I have responsibilities.
To history.
What if you could
have helped Schliemann
discover the city of Troy,
or been with M'tell
when she first
stepped on Ya'seem?
How can anything compare?
May I sleep on it?
Dream not of today,
Mr. Picard.
"Dream not of today?"
The night blessing
of the Yash-El.
As I recall,
you missed that question
on your final exam.
Well, I've had a few years
to look it up.
Professor,
the Enterprise is yours
for as long as you're here.
Thank you.
Dream not of today.
( door chimes )
Come.
Good morning.
Looks like you've
been up for a while.
Yes.
Let's hear it.
( sighs )
I had a long talk with
Professor Galen last night,
and he asked me to leave
the Enterprise
and to join him in
an archaeological expedition
which could last for
nearly a year.
That must be tempting.
I couldn't leave
the Enterprise.
But the offer raised in me
certain feelings of...
regret.
That you could have been
an archaeologist
and not a starship captain?
No, not really.
I'm not sorry for
the path that I chose,
but the professor
did not choose
this gift at random.
The many voices
inside the one.
You see, he knows that the past
is a very insistent voice
inside me,
and this gift is meant
to remind me of that.
And the exploration of space--
surely that must
count for something.
I wouldn't trade it
for anything.
And I would still
make the same choice
that I made all those years ago.
I just wish that I didn't have
to say no to him a second time.
Were you two very close?
I had a father...
but he was like a father
who understood me.
And he had his own children,
but they didn't
follow in his footsteps.
So, I was like the son
who understood him.
And yet, you turned
your back on him.
In a way, I wish that he'd
never come on board the ship.
Good morning, Mr. Picard.
Professor.
The Vulcan ship will
take us as far as DS4.
An Al-Leyan transport is
scheduled to arrive
at the station
three weeks later.
And they'll take us to Caere,
and then we'll use the shuttle
to get us to Indri VIII,
our first stop.
Professor...
I am afraid I won't be going.
The Enterprise
isn't something
that I can leave and
then come back to.
If I go,
I go for good.
And it's not something that
I'm prepared to do.
This is not some
undergraduate
study project that
you're turning down.
This is the chance
of a lifetime.
Don't make the
same mistake twice.
You don't believe that
my career in Starfleet
has been a mistake.
What are you doing
at this very moment?
A study mission!
You're like some Roman centurion
out patrolling the provinces
maintaining a dull
and bloated empire.
We both know that's not true.
I know this.
I know that as a scholar,
you're nothing
but a dilettante.
Years ago, I gave you
the opportunity to become
the foremost archaeologist
of your generation.
Your achievements could
have outstripped even my own
but, no,
you decided to reject
a life of profound
discovery,
and you walked
out on me.
I never wanted to become...
Will you come with me?
I can't.
Then I'll be going.
But, Professor,
you're not scheduled
to catch the Vulcan ship
for another two days.
There's nothing for me here.
Good-bye, Captain.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have completed our mission
in the nebula and are en route
to a diplomatic conference
on Atalia VII.
I must admit,
I have lost my enthusiasm
for those proceedings.
At our present speed,
we will arrive
at the Atalia system
in 37 hours.
Captain?
I'm going for a walk
in the arboretum.
I wouldn't mind
some company.
WORF:
Captain?
A distress call from
Professor Galen's shuttle.
On screen.
Enterprise, I'm being boarded!
Transmission
has been blocked.
I have located
the shuttle, sir.
It is under attack.
Take us out of warp.
On screen.
WORF:
A Yridian destroyer.
Battle stations!
Aye, sir.
Professor Galen is still
inside his vessel, sir.
His life signs are
barely registering.
Get him out of there.
The shuttle is enveloped
by a tractor beam.
The transporter
cannot penetrate it.
Hail the Yridians.
They are not responding.
( alarms blaring )
Return phaser fire.
Disable their offensive systems.
Worf!
I don't understand, Commander.
The phaser blast
was not powerful enough
to destroy the ship.
Transporter Room One,
lock onto Professor Galen
and transport him
directly to Sick Bay.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
He took a disrupter hit
point-blank.
There is nothing I can do.
( monitor beeping )
Jean-Luc...
I was too harsh.
( steady tone )
I'd say at least
three Yridians
boarded the
professor's shuttle.
What did they want?
We're not sure,
but it looks like
they were trying to download
something from his computer.
When he was attacked,
Professor Galen began
to protect certain files
in his computer memory.
We were able to
partially reconstruct
the shuttle's computer,
so at least we have
some of those files.
We found 19 different blocks
of numbers like this one.
What do they mean?
They could mean anything.
Unless we narrow
the parameters of the search,
it would be almost impossible
for the computer
to identify the pattern
with any accuracy.
We tried every
decryption key on record
in case Professor Galen
was using some kind of code,
but we still can't make
heads or tails of them.
Were the Yridians able to
get the number blocks?
At least some of them.
It's impossible
to know how many.
Apparently, the Yridians knew
more about the professor's work
than we do.
They may have known
what these numbers mean.
Well, if they did,
that information died with them.
Not necessarily.
The Yridians
are information dealers.
They may have been delivering
these number blocks
to someone else.
Did they send a signal
before they were destroyed?
No, sir.
We detected no transmissions.
And there were no other ships
in the vicinity.
Did the shuttle's
flight log show
where Galen had been
before coming to the Enterprise?
Yes, sir, the logs indicate
Professor Galen visited
an unexplored
star system-- Ruah IV.
What's the distance
from our present position?
Four days at warp six, sir.
The conference can wait.
Set a course
for the Ruah system.
Standard orbit, Ensign.
Ruah IV is a class-M planet.
67% of its surface
is covered with water.
Its land mass contains
multiple animal species,
including a genus
of proto-hominids.
Scan for earthworks
and monuments
that might indicate
a previous civilization.
There is nothing to indicate
former occupancy
by even
a primitive culture, sir.
Then what was the
foremost archaeologist
in the Federation
doing here?
He left the Enterprise in a
Vulcan ship for Deep Space 4,
and then an Al-Leyan transport
to Caere, and then the shuttle
to Indri VIII.
Mr. Data, what do we know
about Indri VIII?
The Indri system
was first identified
by Federation vessels
nearly 60 years ago.
The eighth planet is L-class.
It is covered with
deciduous vegetation,
unexplored, with no apparent
evidence of civilizations,
either past or present.
The planet possesses
no animal life whatsoever.
Number One, we will proceed
to Indri VIII.
With all due respect, sir,
we've already run
into one dead end.
Indri VIII doesn't seem
much more promising.
And we're late for the
conference on Atalia VII.
I'm aware of the Federation's
timetable, Number One.
Professor Galen visited
here a few days ago,
and he was on his way to
Indri VIII when he was killed.
There is some connection
between these two planets.
I'm going to find it.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, lay in a course for
Indri VIII, warp seven.
( door chimes )
Come.
How's it going?
I thought that if I stared
at these number blocks
long enough,
then I would begin to
see some kind of pattern.
So far...
Nothing.
I meant,
how's it going with you?
If I had gone with him--
Captain, you can't start
thinking like that.
You didn't abandon him.
You chose not to abandon
a lifelong career.
It was the right decision,
and in no way
responsible
for his death.
I realize that.
I know how much
the professor meant to you,
and how much you want to
find out what happened.
But staring at these numbers
isn't going to
bring him back.
The conference
on Atalia VII
has been scheduled
for six months.
Starfleet is relying on
your mediation efforts to--
Counselor, this is
not simply a case
of me taking the Enterprise
and its crew
on some wild goose chase
to purge myself of
guilt and remorse.
I will not let Galen's death
be in vain.
Now, if that means
inconveniencing
a few squabbling delegates
for a few days, then so be it.
I will take
the full responsibility.
Captain.
( sighs )
We're about to enter
the Indri system, sir.
Riker to Picard.
We are approaching
Indri VIII.
PICARD:
On my way.
Sensors are picking up
severe atmospheric fluctuations
on the planet.
RIKER:
Assume a high orbit.
On screen, Mr. Worf.
WORF:
Some sort of plasma reaction
is consuming the
lower atmosphere.
Can we stop it?
No, sir.
The reaction is global.
All life on the planet
is being destroyed, sir.
Why would anyone
want to destroy all the life
on an uninhabited,
neutral planet
with no strategic
importance whatsoever?
"All the life..."
Perhaps the professor's
number blocks
had something to do
with organic matter.
If we narrow the
search parameters
to the biological database,
it might increase
the chances of the
computer finding a match.
I'll be in the lab.
COMPUTER:
Pattern match found.
Specify.
COMPUTER: The number blocks are
mathematical representations
of fragments of
deoxyribonucleic acid strands.
DNA fragments?
Each a different life-form
from 19 different worlds.
The planets that these
fragments are from
are scattered
across the quadrant.
No wonder it took the
professor so long
to collect them, but why?
Wait a minute.
These fragments all seem to have
similar protein configurations.
They may be
chemically compatible.
But how can that be possible?
They're different species
from different planets.
There should be
no compatibility at all.
I know, but look at the
base pair combinations--
they're uniform.
If I'm right...
Computer,
connect the DNA fragments
according to protein link
compatibility.
What is it?
I have no idea.
This is not part of a
natural design, Captain.
This is part of
an algorithm
coded at the
molecular level.
An algorithm?
Are you saying that these
DNA fragments are elements
in some kind of
computer program?
I know how it sounds,
but there's no way
this could be
a random formation.
This is definitely
part of a program.
This fragment has been part
of every DNA strand on Earth
since life began there,
and the other fragments
are just as old.
Someone must have written
this program
over four billion years ago.
So... four billion years ago
someone scattered
this genetic material
into the primordial soup
of at least 19 different planets
across the galaxy?
DATA: The genetic information
must have been incorporated
into the earliest life-forms
on these planets
and then passed down
through each generation.
But why would anyone do this
in the first place?
And what was this
program designed to do?
Well, we couldn't know
that until we assembled
the entire program
and ran it.
We've tried all
of the DNA material
in the Federation computer,
but we haven't been able
to come up with any compatible
protein configurations.
Then, they must be from
worlds outside the Federation.
Mr. Data, how many people
on the Enterprise
are from
non-Federation planets?
17, sir.
You know, this may
be a long shot,
but we should check
each one of these 17 people
to see if they have the correct
protein configuration.
I'll begin collecting
DNA samples now.
You know, Captain,
I've been thinking.
Somebody else must know
about this program.
I bet one of the missing
fragments was on Indri VIII,
and that's why
it was destroyed.
To keep us from finding
that piece of the puzzle.
Mm-hmm.
It's four billion
years old--
a computer program from a
highly-advanced civilization.
And it's hidden in the very
fabric of life itself.
Whatever information
this program contains
could be the most profound
discovery of our time...
or the most dangerous.
And the professor knew that.
( sighs )
They all came up negative.
Well, I have been
through every page
in the professor's
published works
looking for some clue
as to where to go next.
So far, nothing.
Maybe we've been
at this too long.
Why don't we get
some sleep
and start again
tomorrow morning?
I was in the neighborhood.
Hmm?
When I asked the professor
why he went all the way to Kurl,
he said,
"I was in the neighborhood."
Doing what?
Collecting DNA samples.
There's only one planet
in the Kurlan system
capable of supporting life--
Loren III.
No.
There is no Loren III sample
from the data downloaded
from the professor's shuttle.
If he did have one,
it must have been taken
by the Yridians
when they attacked.
Mr. Data, set a course for
Loren III, maximum warp.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
We are approaching
the Loren system.
RIKER:
Slow to half impulse.
Take us into orbit
above the third planet.
There is a good chance
that our competition
may be here before us.
Battle stations,
Mr. Worf.
Aye.
We are now entering orbit.
PICARD:
On screen.
RIKER:
You were right, Captain.
We've got company--
Cardassians.
They are hailing us.
On screen.
My name is Gul Ocett.
Identify yourself,
and state your business
in this star system.
I am Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise,
and I see no reason
why I should answer to you.
Cardassians have no claims
in this sector.
I suppose not.
But my admittedly
hasty estimate
shows one Federation starship
and two Cardassian war vessels.
Perhaps I have miscounted.
Not at all.
But we are on a purely
scientific mission.
You have no reason
to interfere with us.
And you have nothing to lose
by delaying a purely scientific
mission for a few days.
I invite you to withdraw.
Captain, Klingon
attack cruiser decloaking
off the starboard bow.
They are hailing us.
KLINGON: This is the
Klingon vessel Maht-H'a.
What are you
doing here?
Captain's Log, supplemental.
It seems that we have not one
but two competitors
in our attempt to complete
Professor Galen's puzzle.
I have prevailed upon the
Cardassian and Klingon Captains
to meet with me.
I believe we all know
why we're here.
If we can admit that,
then we can move forward.
We were merely
scouting the planet
for possible colonization.
Pah! A ridiculous story.
What were you
doing here, then?
Scientific research.
Ha!
Look, if we try to
deceive one another,
then we shall
get nowhere.
I think we all know
about Professor Galen's
research...
and about the computer program
composed of
DNA fragments.
I will take your silence
as a confirmation.
Now, it stands to reason
that none of us have
the DNA fragments
necessary
to complete the program.
You were the first to arrive
in this system.
Do you have an organic sample
from the planet below?
Yes, and I will fire on anyone
who attempts to obtain
another one.
As if we fear
Cardassian threats.
I believe that one of you has
a fragment from Indri VIII.
KLINGON:
Yes.
And there will be
no other samples
from Indri VIII.
What is that supposed to mean?
He destroyed
the biosphere of the planet
after he had taken the sample.
( hissing )
Typical Klingon thinking--
take what you want
and destroy the rest.
PICARD: We're all missing
some of the fragments--
not necessarily the same ones.
But unless we combine
the ones we have,
we will never learn
the secret of the program.
There is no secret.
It is an ancient weapon design
of incredible power.
And the Klingon Empire
will not allow it
to fall into
an enemy's hands--
or even a friend's.
A weapon?
The Yridian who sold us
the information
claimed that
the program would yield
the key to an unlimited
power source.
But until we assemble it,
we will never know its purpose.
He's right.
As far as we know, it might
just be a recipe for biscuits.
Biscuits?
If that is what you believe,
then go back to Cardassia.
I will send you
my mother's recipe.
How dare you!
PICARD: Mev yap!
Enough!
Without cooperation,
we will get nowhere.
What do you propose?
If you each bring your samples
on board the Enterprise,
I will combine them with ours.
And then we will all observe
the results simultaneously,
giving no one the advantage.
And if we refuse?
Then this endeavor dies here
in this room.
Captain.
KLINGON:
Excellent.
CRUSHER:
There's still one missing piece.
Pahk! We have
surrendered
what we had
for nothing.
You are remarkably
shortsighted, Nu'Daq.
We are closer to the
answer than we were.
We may be very much
closer, indeed.
NU'DAQ:
How can that be?
We have no idea where
to start looking
for the missing
DNA fragment.
This is a jigsaw puzzle
whose pieces are scattered
across the galaxy.
Doesn't it make it
natural to assume
that the original designers
of the puzzle
should want us to find it?
Why else would they have put
the pieces in our DNA?
And, in turn,
wouldn't that suggest
that they would try to
make it easy for us
to find those pieces?
That there might be some
pattern to the distribution?
The computer might be able
to find that pattern.
Doctor, program the
computer to analyze
the distribution of the
pieces that we have,
correcting for changes
in star configurations
over four billion years.
Then extrapolate for
the missing piece.
That's going to take
several hours to set up
and to process.
Excuse me.
If you wish, you can stay
on board while we wait.
I intend to.
( conversations and laughter )
Good evening,
Commander Data.
Captain.
Is there any word yet
on the missing fragment?
The computer is
processing the data.
I will be notified as soon
as there is any information.
Ah... Commander,
your reputation
for physical strength
is known
even in the
Klingon Empire.
You are familiar with
the B'aht Qul challenge?
I am familiar with
many Klingon rituals,
including the B'aht Qul.
Ahh...
Haa.
Wa'... cha'...
Wej.
Maw' tok!
( grunting )
My upper spinal support
is a polyalloy
designed to withstand
extreme stress.
My skull is composed
of cortenide and duranium.
( grunting )
I understand your
intellectual prowess
is equally impressive.
If I were to learn
of the results
from the computer search
before the others,
the Klingon Empire would
have a strategic advantage.
A being of your abilities
would go far
in the Empire.
You are attempting
to bribe me.
Not at all.
You suggested a plan
that would work
to your advantage--
one that I would be
capable of executing.
You then implied
a reward.
Clearly, you were--
Commander... never mind.
( beeping )
What the hell?
Computer,
run a level-3 diagnostic
on the primary
defensive systems.
La Forge to Captain Picard.
PICARD:
What is it, Geordi?
You might wanna
come down here.
I found something
that I think you should see.
The computer has completed
its analysis.
The computer was able
to extrapolate
this geometric pattern
based on the distribution
of the fragments.
Computer, highlight the section
of the missing pattern.
The missing DNA fragment
should be in this system.
The star is in Sector 21459--
the Rahm-Izad system.
( low growl )
Direct hit on
our port nacelle.
They are powering up
for another volley.
Let's make it look good.
Ensign, release the
inertial dampers.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
They are firing.
Report, Number One.
The power boost to the
structural integrity field
protected the nacelles.
We used the inertial dampers
to simulate complete
shield failure.
It is fortunate
that your engineer
discovered
Gul Ocett's attempt
to tamper with your
defensive systems.
Maht-H'a, status.
KLINGON: Minor damage
to starboard nacelle.
We will be operational
in less than one hour.
What?!
You incompetent toh-pah!
You were supposed
to be prepared.
The Cardassian vessels have
set a course for Rahm-Izad.
Well, it won't take them
long to realize
that Rahm-Izad
is the wrong planet.
Captain, you're very
welcome to join us.
I... will go with you.
Ensign, set in a course for
the Vilmoran system, warp nine.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
Engage.
I am scanning all seven planets
of the Vilmoran system.
None appears
to support life.
How can that be?
The professor's data depends--
Correction-- the second
planet shows evidence
of an ancient ocean, now dry.
It once supported life?
Yes, and it still may,
in a limited fashion,
not detectable
by our long-range sensors.
Lay in a course, Ensign.
Full impulse.
Riker to Transporter Room One.
Captain, we've located a planet
that may still support life.
We'll know in a minute.
Any sign of the Cardassians?
RIKER: Not yet,
but we don't know how long
it'll stay that way.
Acknowledged.
I am reading a small pocket
of vegetative life--
a primitive lichen growing
in a fossilized seabed.
Transporter Room One, I am
programming the coordinates.
Stand by.
There. Over there.
RIKER:
Captain, we've got company.
I'm ready to pull you
out of there.
PICARD: Wait for
my order, Number One.
( whoosh of active transport )
You dishonorable toh-pah.
Perhaps we could exchange
insults some other time.
I'm rather
busy now.
Well... it was
quite a chase,
wasn't it,
my friends?
How--
ROMULAN: We intercepted
several communiques between
the Yridians and Cardassia.
My ship was watching under cloak
when Professor Galen's
shuttle was attacked.
And you have been
shadowing us ever since.
And now,
the reward.
Step clear, please.
I shall destroy the
entire rock face
and every trace
of DNA with it.
You will go back to
Romulus empty-handed.
Your superiors will
be quite pleased.
Perhaps we could come
to a compromise?
You give us the gene code
and the Romulans...
( whispering )
The seabed--
it may be only
partially fossilized.
It could still contain
organic material.
OCETT: ...particularly
strong bargaining...
Which would still
contain the DNA.
NU'DAQ: I have been
searching for the answer
as long as anyone.
I will not be
eliminated now.
ROMULAN: You can be
eliminated by a disrupter.
Now, what do you
say to my offer?
How can I be sure you won't
kill me if I acquiesce?
I've given you my word.
Etched in stone,
no doubt.
No deals!
There will be no deals
as long as I am
still alive.
ROMULAN: Do not
press me, Klingon.
I don't care whether
you live or die.
WORF: If you fire,
others will, also.
Many will die.
ROMULAN:
We have superior numbers.
PICARD: The program
has been activated.
I think it's reconfiguring
the tricorder.
We will die
together, brother.
Tash-koh-tah.
It's modifying
the diode emitter
to project something.
You are wondering
who we are,
why we have done this,
how it is come that
I stand before you--
the image of a being
from so long ago.
Life evolved
at my planet
before all others
in this part of the galaxy.
We left our world,
explored the stars,
and found none
like ourselves.
Our civilization
thrived for ages.
But what is the life
of one race
compared to the vast
stretches of cosmic time?
We knew that one day,
we would be gone
that nothing
of us would survive.
So, we left you.
Our scientists seeded
the primordial oceans
of many worlds where life
was in its infancy.
The seed codes directed
your evolution toward
a physical form
resembling ours--
this body you see
before you...
which is, of course,
shaped as yours is shaped--
for you are the end result.
The seed codes also
contained this message,
which was scattered in fragments
on many different worlds.
It was our hope that you
would have to come together
in fellowship and companionship
to hear this message.
And if you can see and hear me
our hope has been
fulfilled.
You are a monument...
not to our greatness,
but to our
existence.
That was our wish--
that you, too,
would know life,
and would keep alive
our memory.
There is something
of us in each of you,
and so, something of you
in each other.
Remember us.
That's all?!
If she were not dead,
I would kill her.
The very notion that
a Cardassian could have
anything in common
with a Klingon--
it turns my stomach.
Picard to Enterprise.
RIKER:
Standing by, sir.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46735.2.
Our frequent use of high warp
over the last few days
has overextended
the propulsion systems.
We are finishing minor repairs
before returning
to Federation territory.
It's a shame
Professor Galen
didn't live to see the
end result of his study.
I can't think of anyone who
would have appreciated it more.
If it hadn't
been for you
his dream to
solve that puzzle
would never have
been realized.
You left him a
wonderful legacy.
Yes, but it would have been
a more fitting legacy
if the message had not
fallen on such deaf ears.
Hmm. You never know.
Hmm.
Well...
( sighs )
I have to get
this day started.
Both of us.
See you this afternoon.
Riker to Captain Picard.
Incoming transmission
from the Romulan command ship.
PICARD:
Put it through.
Acknowledged.
Captain, my ships are leaving
orbit for Romulan space.
Until our next encounter.
Until then.
It would seem that we are not
completely dissimilar after all
in our hopes,
or in our fears.
Yes.
Well, then, perhaps...
one day...
One day.