You're absolutely right,
Doctor.
Right now...
I can't imagine
ever hurting anybody.
DOCTOR:
How do you feel
about that person
you used to be?
I feel terrible,
but thanks to you,
I'm... I'm doing much better now
and I'm... confident
that when I leave
I will be ready
to take my place in society.
And when do you think
that will be?
Well, now.
Right away.
Why do you say that?
Well, you said
that when I was able to...
accept what I'd done
and I understood
the consequences of my actions
that I would be...
I would be free to go.
"Free to go."
You mean
you don't think
you should stand trial
for what you did.
No, I'm looking forward
to proving my innocence.
I thought you said
you accepted what you did.
No.
That's-that's not
what I meant.
( Riker sighs )
I was sick when it happened.
I wasn't responsible
for what I did.
How do I know you're
not just telling me
what I want to hear?
Perhaps we should continue
this discussion next week.
No. I-I want to talk
about this now.
You're starting
to sound angry again.
Maybe you need
another treatment.
What I need is to get
out of this cell.
I've been locked
in here for... for days.
You've controlled
my every move.
You've told... you've told me
what to eat and what to think
and what to say, and then...
when I show a glimmer
of independent thought
you strap me down,
you inject me with drugs.
You call it a "treatment."
You're becoming
agitated.
You bet I'm agitated.
I may be surrounded
by insanity,
but I'm not insane
and there's any...
there isn't...
there's nothing you...
( laughs softly )
I'm sorry.
Could-could we go back to, uh...
to "you're
becoming agitated"?
No. Why don't we take
a break for tonight?
I think we've made
a lot of progress.
I'm still not comfortable
with that last speech.
There's such a thing
as over-rehearsing, Will.
You're going to be fine.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just not right
for this part.
Most humanoids
have the potential
to be irrational.
Perhaps you
should attempt
to access that part
of your psyche.
Thank you, Data.
Your character feels
at odds with everyone--
as if the world's
against him.
Like my first year
at the Academy.
Yes. That's what your
character is going through
but I want you,
Will Riker, to relax.
I'll do my best.
It'll be wonderful.
You're going to knock 'em dead.
Right.
( door opens )
You control my every move.
You tell me what to say,
what to think,
what to eat, what to say
what to think, what to eat.
And then when I show a glimmer
of independent thought
you strap me down,
inject me with drugs
call it a "treatment."
I may be surrounded by insanity,
but I am not insane.
Excuse me.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Tilonus IV?
Didn't their government
just collapse?
It's in a state
of total anarchy.
When the prime minister
was assassinated
a Federation research team
was on the planet.
It's believed that they
were forced into hiding.
Will, your mission will be to
locate and to evacuate them.
Can't they go
to the local authorities?
There are no
local authorities.
The government is splintered.
It seems that... there are
various factions vying for power
and they're desperate
for weapons
or technology of any kind.
Apparently, some of the factions
have resorted to torture
to gather
their information.
Well, a Starfleet research team
would be a prime target.
Then I'll have to go
down there alone, undercover.
Agreed.
Mr. Worf is ready to give you
a detailed briefing
on Tilonian culture.
Well, I guess
I'll have to back out
of Beverly's play after all.
Oh, no. No, there will be
plenty of time for that.
We don't arrive at Tilonus
for another five days.
And besides,
if you back out
she'll come after me
to play the part.
This is the last
known location
of the research team.
They had occupied
a small building
in the southwest
quarter of the city.
You will begin
your search there.
The southwest quarter is
over 200 square kilometers.
That's a lot of land
for one man to cover.
I guess I'd better pack
an extra pair of boots.
This apparel will help you
pass as a common merchant.
This Tilonian pendant
is equipped with
a communicator circuit.
Hmm... doesn't really
match the outfit.
I suggest you pay closer
attention, Commander.
Your life will
be at stake.
Do you understand
what I am saying?
Of course I do.
Because you will be
posing as a merchant
you will need to know
how to use the nisroh
for the traditional
bartering ceremony.
You will be judged on your
prowess with the blade.
I-I'm sorry, Commander.
I did not intend...
It's okay.
I guess I really wasn't
paying attention.
I'd better go to Sick Bay.
We'll continue this later.
Boy, you will do anything
to get out of
doing this play
but you're going to
have to do something
better than this.
The play's not
till tomorrow night.
I've still got 24 hours.
( regenerator whirring )
Well, don't get any ideas.
I will see you onstage
at 1800 hours.
Right.
Oh... it still hurts.
( tricorder beeping )
There was no damage
to the nerves,
so you shouldn't
be feeling any pain.
Probably just a symptom
of stage fright.
CREWMAN:
Oh! It hurts! Oh!
He was working on
a conduit on deck 39.
A plasma torch blew
up in his hands.
Oh, it hurts. Please!
Hypospray.
Yes, Doctor.
( groaning )
CRUSHER:
Get me 20cc's of leporazine.
Treat the
surface burns
with the anabolic proto-plaser.
Yes, Doctor.
WOMAN:
Should we get a stasis unit
on line?
CRUSHER:
Have one standing by
just in case
and get me an epidermal
sample right away.
Begin dermal regeneration
and have tissue regrowth
standing by.
I want him sedated.
I've been on
a lot of missions.
I've seen a lot
of people injured,
but I have never
been affected by
anything like this.
He was looking right at me.
And that was
disturbing to you.
It was as if he was
blaming me for something.
And this wasn't
the only incident.
The last several days
I've felt like everybody's
been staring at me
or talking about me.
It's as if I was
in frame of mind.
"Frame of Mind"?
Beverly's play.
Ever since I began
rehearsing for the role,
I've been uneasy
and restless.
You're probably
drawing on feelings
that you're not used
to expressing.
Right.
The play is full
of disturbing images--
people losing their minds,
being tortured by doctors.
I can't get it
out of my mind.
Sometimes it's healthy
to explore the darker side
of the psyche.
Jung called it
"owning your own shadow."
This could be a sign
that you're a real actor.
This is becoming more
than just a role to you.
Maybe you're right.
Don't be afraid
of your darker side.
Have fun with it.
Who's that?
You just missed him.
Is there a new
lieutenant on board?
I'm not sure.
Do you want me to check
the personnel logs?
No, I'll check them tomorrow.
I'm going to bed early.
The performance
is tomorrow night.
I want to be up for it.
I'm looking forward to it.
Break a leg.
I'll try not to
take you literally.
You're becoming agitated.
You bet I'm agitated!
I may be surrounded
by insanity,
but I am not insane
and nothing you
or anyone else can say
will change that.
And I won't let you
or anyone else
tell me that I am.
You may be able
to destroy my mind,
but you can't change
the fact that I'm innocent.
I didn't kill that man!
And that's
what's driving you crazy.
I can see we have
a lot of work to do.
Nothing you can say will
change the fact I'm innocent!
I'm not crazy!
I'm not crazy.
( applause )
( all shouting bravo )
( applause continues )
Bravo, bravo!
( applause stops abruptly )
I can see we have
a lot of work to do.
Where am I?
How did you get me
off the ship?
The ship again?
What's going on?
I understand
this must be disturbing for you
but try to relax.
Tell me, where were you
a moment ago?
I was on the Enterprise.
I was in the middle of a play.
But it was here.
It was not real,
it was on a stage.
I can assure you,
this is not a stage.
Do you remember your name?
I'm Commander...
Commander...
A second ago, I knew who I was.
I was on the ship,
I was in a play...
and now I'm having trouble
remembering anything.
That's good.
You're starting to come out
of your delusional state.
Delusional?
It was not a delusion.
I was there.
We discussed this.
Do you remember?
We contacted Starfleet
and asked them
about you.
No.
We spoke with Admiral Budrow.
Starbase 29.
He had never heard of me
and they had no officer
that fit
my description.
That's right.
Now, I want you
to focus on who I am.
Do you remember me?
I don't know.
I'm Dr. Syrus.
Do you remember anything
about where you are now?
My head hurts.
Somebody hit me.
You tried to escape.
You struggled with one
of the attendants
and hit your head on a door.
Do you remember that?
Yes.
I remember that now.
But I thought it was a Klingon
who had cut me with a knife.
That's called transposition.
You're projecting elements
from your delusions
onto events
that really happened.
But that's good.
There was a time
when you couldn't break away
from your starship fantasy
at all.
Now...
if what you say is-is true...
where am I?
You're in ward 47
of the Tilonus Institute
for Mental Disorders.
Why am I here?
We'll talk more later.
You don't have to remember
everything today.
You're making
excellent progress.
Wait!
Oh...
( ragged breathing )
MAN:
Good afternoon.
I've got some good news
for you.
Dr. Syrus suggested
that you might enjoy
a couple of hours
in the common area today.
Well?
I guess so.
( door slides open )
I hope you're hungry.
They're serving
spiny lobe-fish today.
You won't need that.
( chuckles )
That's what you said
the last time.
( man screams )
( man yelling )
( patient talking quietly )
( patients talking quietly )
( door buzzer )
I'll be back
with your lunch.
I hear you're
a Starfleet officer.
I'm Commander Bloom
from the Yorktown.
There are at least a dozen
of us here, maybe more.
We were kidnapped--
brought here
against our will.
Sanders was
on the Yosemite.
They did something
to his mind.
I think they're trying
to get neurochemicals
from our brains.
Stafko was with me
on the Yorktown.
I don't know
what they did to him.
We're going to get out of here.
I've made
a communicator.
You have?
Yes.
There are
three starships in orbit.
They're going to beam us out
of here any day now.
I'll ask them
to get you out, too.
Commander Bloom
to Yorktown.
Come in, Yorktown.
I've made contact
with another officer.
Talking to your
starship again, Jaya?
No.
Don't let them tell you
you're crazy.
You know you're not
supposed to take
utensils from
the common area.
You're welcome to try it.
I'm not that far gone, am I?
Of course you are.
( laughing )
Your name is...
Mavek.
That's right.
Not bad for a crazy man.
I am beginning to remember
certain things.
Why am I here?
I remember
when they brought you in.
You were struggling...
screaming.
We could barely
hold you down.
In fact, just getting
the blood off your hands
took over an hour.
Blood?
On your hands,
clothes...
You didn't just kill that man--
you mutilated him.
What are you talking about?
I didn't kill anybody.
I'm afraid you did.
You stabbed him.
They found you near the body,
the knife in your hand.
( whispers ):
No...
that's not true!
Yes, it is.
And if you ever get out of here,
you're going to stand trial.
You're lying!
I imagine
the punishment
will be quite severe
considering you stabbed him
nine times.
( yelling ):
No!
( panting )
( gasps in pain )
( gasps )
I was there.
I was in ward 47,
just like in the play.
Everyone thought
that I was insane
that I had
actually killed someone.
But it was all real.
CRUSHER:
Deanna mentioned that
you went to bed early
because you were feeling
a little anxious about the play,
but I had no idea.
You said that in your dream,
we performed the play.
How did it go?
It was a smash.
We got a standing ovation.
Well, let's hope
it goes that well tonight.
Well, we have one hour
before curtain.
How are you feeling?
I feel like an actor.
Well, you're certainly
beginning to look the part.
Perhaps we should continue
this discussion
next week.
No, I want to talk
about this now.
You're starting to sound
angry again.
Maybe you need
another treatment.
What I need is to
get out of this cell!
I've been locked up
in here for days.
You've controlled
my every move.
You've told me what to eat,
what to think, what to say.
And when I show a glimmer
of independent thought...
of independent thought
you strap me down,
inject me with drugs
and call it a treatment.
You're becoming agitated.
You bet I'm agitated!
I may be surrounded by insanity,
but I am not insane
and there's nothing that you...
( door clangs shut )
What's happening?
I can see we have
a lot of work to do.
Nothing you can do will change
the fact that I'm innocent!
I'm not crazy!
I'm not...
You're the key to all this,
aren't you?
Who are you?!
Lieutenant Suna, sir.
Will, are you
all right?
No... uh... yes...
I don't know.
Why don't we go down
to Sick Bay?
There's nothing wrong
with you neurologically,
and I can't find anything
that could have caused
the hallucinations
but your heart rate
is way up
and your blood pressure
is above normal
and you are
physically exhausted.
This is not a case
of simple fatigue.
Will, you know
that when you're under
conditions of extreme stress
the mind can manufacture
all kinds of things.
Drugs... they injected me
with drugs.
See if there are
drugs in my system.
( sighing )
( tricorder whirring )
Nothing.
In that dream,
they gave me drugs.
Didn't anyone else
at the theater
see anything strange happen
during the performance?
No, nobody.
Get some rest, will.
The play is over.
Don't give it another thought.
Right.
How's Lieutenant Suna?
A little shaken,
but all right.
I feel like
such an idiot.
It's nothing
to be embarrassed about.
We're your friends.
We all know the stress
you've been under.
I'm sure everyone
understands perfectly.
Commander, I must
congratulate you
on your performance
this evening.
Oh?
Your unexpected choice
to improvise
was an effective method
of drawing the audience
into the plight
of your character.
You gave a
truly realistic
interpretation
of multi-infarct dementia.
Thank you.
Well, maybe not
everyone understands.
I think I'd better
get a little rest,
clear my mind a little.
I want you to try
some relaxation
techniques as well.
Remember the ones
I showed you a
few months ago?
They never seem to work for me.
SYRUS:
Maybe you need
another treatment.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Will, I want you
to get some sleep.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
( doors open )
It's not real.
It's not real!
Don't let them tell you
you're crazy.
( door clangs shut )
No!
Let me out of here!
Help me!
Help me.
( ragged sigh )
I need help.
I don't want to be at the mercy
of these hallucinations
anymore.
So you've accepted
you're not from a starship
that it's all a delusion?
All I know is when I
go back to the ship
reality breaks apart,
nothing makes sense,
and then when it's over,
it fades away like a dream.
But when I'm in the hospital
everything here
seems real,
and I remember
everything that
happens here.
And what about
how you got here?
Maybe I did kill someone.
I don't know...
But I want to know how.
I'm glad to hear
you say that
because I just had
a long talk
with the hospital
administrator.
He told me there are
certain legal questions
that have to be resolved
relatively soon.
Meaning?
Meaning we can't keep you
here much longer.
We're the only
mental health facility
on Tilonus IV.
We have many people
who need our help.
I don't want to put
any undue stress on you,
but we have to settle this case
one way or another
within the next few days.
What does that mean?
You're facing a choice.
We can try to help you
remember what happened
using reflection therapy.
If it's successful
you'd be fit
to stand trial.
Reflection therapy?
It's a way
for you to interact
with the various facets
of your personality.
We scan
the regions of your brain
that control
emotions and memory
and then project them
holographically.
And what is
the second option?
A complete
synaptic reconstruction
of your cerebral cortex.
Surgery.
We would neutralize
the synaptic pathways
responsible
for your mental instability.
And it doesn't sound
like you care for that option.
I don't.
The procedure is irreversible.
You'd be left with a completely
altered personality.
The person you are now
would cease to exist.
Option one is beginning
to sound better.
I agree.
Reflection therapy, then.
When do we begin?
This afternoon,
if you're ready.
I want you to understand
that this isn't going
to be easy.
You'll be interacting
with aspects of your psyche
you've never
dealt with before
and...
and you may be disturbed
by what they have to say.
Close your eyes.
Try to relax.
Clear your mind.
( whirring )
Now... think back
to before you came
to the hospital...
But don't try to remember
specific incidents.
Concentrate on
how you felt.
( inhales and exhales )
I was afraid.
Terrified.
She was with me
on the ship.
That's because
she represents
an aspect
of your personality
and there are
many parts of you
that still believe
you're on
that starship.
Why her?
I asked you to get in touch
with your feelings
and this is the part of you
that responded.
Talk to her
about how you felt
before you came here.
You said I was terrified.
Of what?
I was in a dark place--
cold... frightened.
Someone was there.
Who?
I felt threatened
by them, trapped.
You're doing very well.
Now, let's try
to find out
how you responded
to these feelings.
Try to focus on your actions.
You felt trapped.
What did you do?
I was angry.
They were attacking me.
I fought back.
I felt pain.
I was injured.
I began to panic.
There was a struggle, and I...
You what?
What happened?
Try to associate
your actions and emotions
with logical thoughts.
What do you think
caused you to act
and feel this way?
It was cold
and dark...
because...
I was outdoors
at night.
I was in
a narrow place.
I was walking
through an alley.
I felt threatened.
I was being watched.
Someone must have followed me
into the alley.
That's why I started
to walk faster.
Someone grabbed me
from behind.
I panicked.
I tried to fight them off.
How many of them
were there?
Three-- humanoid.
I only saw the face
of one of them.
What did he look like?
I saw him
on the ship, too.
I also saw him
here in the hospital,
but I don't
know who he is.
That's Mr. Suna,
the hospital administrator.
You met him
when you first arrived here.
What part of me
does he represent?
I don't know.
Don't believe this,
Will.
None of it's real.
You're with us
on the Enterprise.
Doctor?
PICARD:
We're your colleagues.
You can trust us.
Everything will
be all right.
Do you have anything
to say to them?
( heavy breathing )
You're all delusions.
Do not listen
to him, Commander.
He is trying
to trick you.
You are
in danger here.
Let us help you.
TROI:
Listen to me, Will.
In all the years
we've known each other
have I ever lied to you?
No... please...
leave me alone!
Will... please?
No!
( crying )
You've taken a big step today.
You finally turned
your back on
those delusions
and all that they
represent to you.
We'll continue later.
( heavy sigh )
( door buzzer )
( beeping )
( door clangs shut )
It's not real.
Commander,
do you know who I am?
Do you know where you are?
If you can't answer,
just listen.
You were
on an undercover mission
to Tilonus IV,
something happened.
We were told
that you killed somebody.
We do not believe
it's true.
We're being blocked
at every turn.
The hospital administrator
denies you're here at all.
We are beginning to think
that there's some sort
of conspiracy going on.
I had to come in here
posing as a health official.
Sit tight, Commander.
We are going to get you
out of here.
( sighing )
Not real.
( rattling )
( footsteps )
( door opening )
Commander...
Get away from me.
Commander, you
must come with us.
You are in danger here.
No!
WORF:
Silence!
( groaning )
Commander,
are you all right?
Help me!
Who are you?
Take them to
Security Ward.
Worf to Enterprise.
The pattern enhancer
has been activated.
Three to beam up.
MAN:
Acknowledged.
( tricorder whirring )
( beeping )
There's damage
to the parietal lobe.
It's as if someone's trying
to access his long-term memory,
and he's in a severe state
of neural shock.
It's going to take him
a while to recover.
Number One,
do you remember
what happened?
You were abducted during
the mission to Tilonus IV.
You were put
into a psychiatric hospital.
It's still bleeding.
It's minor.
Don't worry about it.
( whirring )
We have been checking
on the hospital administrator.
Mr. Suna.
It appears that he's involved
with one of the rival factions.
We believe
that he is responsible
for what happened to you.
It still hurts.
It's bleeding again.
Why?
You just healed it.
Will, try to calm down.
This isn't real.
What are you doing, Will?
If I'm right,
you're not really here.
This isn't a real phaser.
It's all a fantasy,
and I'm going to end it
no matter what it takes.
And what if it
isn't a fantasy?
Are you willing
to take that chance?
You're right.
I won't.
But I'm going to find out
what's real and what's not.
Will, don't do it!
( glass shattering )
How is he progressing?
Syrus:
He's not responding
to the reflection therapy.
His delusions
are growing more elaborate.
He broke out
of his cell last night.
We found him running
down a corridor
claiming people
had come to take him
back to his starship.
Then, I see no other choice.
We'll have to perform
the synaptic
reconstruction.
I still have a phaser.
Why do I still have a phaser?
It's not a phaser--
it's a knife.
You stole it
from one of
the food trays.
Give it to me.
We don't want you
to hurt yourself.
( groans )
I don't believe you.
( glass shattering )
If this is a knife,
what happened to Mavek?
It's very complicated.
I'll answer all your questions,
but first I want you
to put that down.
No. If this is a real phaser,
then I was on the Enterprise,
but I fired it
on myself
so I should be dead.
None of this is real.
I'm setting this to level 16.
Wide field.
That should destroy
half of this building.
Unless, of course,
this isn't a real phaser.
( glass shattering )
It's all about
you, isn't it?
You're the only constant
the only person
in both places.
There's a lot more going on
here than you realize.
This isn't real, either.
What's happening to me?
Listen to me.
We can still save you,
but you must stop fighting us.
( groans )
You're lying.
Let me help you.
No!
I'm warning you...
( audience yelling, "bravo!" )
( glass shattering )
( beeping )
He's conscious.
I haven't finished
the neuro drain!
Get him sedated!
Riker to Enterprise.
WORF:
Enterprise here.
Are you all right, sir?
Emergency transport.
Get me out of here.
( angry grunt )
PICARD:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46778.1.
Commander Riker
has returned safely
from his mission
to Tilonus IV.
Dr. Crusher has repaired
the damage
to his long-term memory.
Evidently, you were abducted
two days after beaming
to the surface.
I remember now.
I was in an alley.
They attacked me from behind.
I tried to fight them off
with a nisroh
that Worf had given me.
I managed to get one
of them off me,
but I think they injected me
with some sort of drug.
We believe that
they were trying
to extract strategic
information
from your memory
using a neurosomatic technique.
I was in a hospital, then I was
back on the Enterprise,
then I was back
in the hospital.
I kept shifting
from place to place.
I couldn't tell
what was real.
Your mind must
have created a
defense mechanism
that helped you resist
the neurosomatic
process.
Your unconscious fastened on
to elements of your real life
in an attempt to
keep you grounded
to keep you sane.
The preparation
for the mission,
the play.
Those were recent memories
fresh in my mind.
You should get some rest.
We can talk
some more tomorrow.
There is one thing
I'd like to do first.
Are you sure you want
to do this by yourself?
The stage crew and I
were going to do it
tomorrow morning.
I'm positive.
After everything
that I've experienced
I don't think I could sleep
knowing it was still up.