( door chimes )
( beeps )
( sighs )
All right. Come in.
Guinan.
What's wrong?
I need a doctor.
Geordi beat me in
straight sets today.
I think I've developed
tennis elbow.
Well, you better go
to Sick Bay.
I think Dr. Selar
is on duty.
I don't want
to see Dr. Selar.
I always see you.
I'm very particular
about my doctors.
Well, you better
get a new one
because I'm not a doctor
on this ship anymore.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
Three days on a shuttle
to Starbase 23,
a transport
back to Earth...
I can hear
Admiral Brooks now
telling me how
I've disgraced
Starfleet Medical.
Then, a leisurely
day and a half
before the formal
inquiry begins
and my career ends.
Beverly...
my elbow.
Your elbow.
Let me see it.
Does this hurt?
Ow! Yes,
right there.
That's tennis elbow,
all right.
Here. Hold your arm
like this.
You know,
I've never been to
a formal inquiry.
Well, I'll see if I can
arrange one for you.
All you have to do
is disobey orders,
violate medical ethics
and cause an
interstellar incident.
Well, I guess
that would do it.
Make a fist.
Do I have to hit you
with my fist
before you tell me
what happened?
It all started
when those scientists
came on board.
No. It started
when I got curious.
Well, there's nothing
wrong with that.
That's why I went to
the Altine conference.
I'd heard about a new
subspace technology,
developed by a Ferengi--
a Dr. Reyga.
A Ferengi scientist.
Hmm.
His invention was based
on metaphasic fields
but his methodology was
completely unorthodox.
Well,
I like unorthodox.
Too bad
you weren't there.
Nobody else would
listen to him.
They all but jeered
him off the stage.
But I had read
his paper
and his work
was extraordinary.
So you gathered
all these scientists
to come hear
this Ferengi.
Yes. I hoped I could
be a facilitator.
I thought that if
I invited scientists
from various cultures
to board the Enterprise
I could sit them down
and help them
to understand
the value of his ideas.
Like a scientific
diplomat.
Exactly.
So, after persuading
the captain
I had to round up
as many scientists
as I could
from the field of
subspace technology.
But of all the scientists
I invited,
only four were interested
in hearing about
Dr. Reyga's invention,
and I wasn't
altogether sure
that they were going
to be compatible.
Kurak was
a warp field specialist
on the Klingon homeworld.
I don't think Klingons regard
scientists very highly.
She always seemed
a little defensive.
Dr. T'pan is
practically a legend
in the field of
subspace morphology.
She's been the director
of the Vulcan science academy
for 15 years.
Her husband, Dr. Christopher,
came with her.
I didn't know
much about him,
but he was some kind
of subspace theoretician.
Jo'bril was a Takaran,
the first one I'd ever met.
I had no idea
what to expect from him.
And then there was Dr. Reyga,
the Ferengi scientist.
You've all seen
my experimental data.
The metaphasic shield
has been proven.
Forgive
my skepticism, doctor,
but your claims are
somewhat extravagant.
Protect a shuttle
within a star's corona?
Not even your own government
believes it can be done.
That's why I've
invited you all here.
You have the vision
to see the potential
of Dr. Reyga's
metaphasic shield.
I need help to develop
the shield.
I am willing to grant
exclusive rights
to whoever provides
the necessary resources.
I think you all realize
what this shielding
process could mean.
The possibilities of exploration
and research are endless.
But only
if it works.
I'm not convinced that
this metaphasic shield
can withstand
either the temperature
or the radiation
it would be exposed to.
But it has-- not only
in countless simulations
but in a field test
that I conducted myself.
For which, of course,
we have only your word.
REYGA:
Are you accusing me
of falsifying my data?
KURAK:
You would not be
the first scientist
to manipulate experimental
data to his own advantage.
Dr. Reyga has offered
to demonstrate
his invention.
He's outfitted
one of our shuttles
with his metaphasic
shield.
I will take it
into the corona
of the star Vaytan.
That star has
a superdense corona.
The shuttle
would be subjected
to particularly
intense radiation.
Perhaps it would
be wise to choose
a star of lesser
magnitude.
I agree.
My own research into
solar energy transfer
suggests that Vaytan's corona
is extremely unstable.
What better way
to test my invention?
I'm not concerned.
The shield will hold.
I, for one, would feel
more comfortable
if someone else
flew the shuttle--
someone more objective.
JO'BRIL:
I will volunteer
for that task.
I've spent years studying
solar plasma reactions.
The thought of being able to
penetrate a star's corona...
it is a remarkable
opportunity.
I've studied
your data, Dr. Reyga.
I think you're on solid
scientific ground.
I do not share your
optimism, Dr. Jo'bril,
but if you wish
to pilot the craft
I would be more confident
in your assessment of
the shield than Dr. Reyga's.
CHRISTOPHER:
I agree.
At this point, we need
an impartial evaluation.
We'll need to be sure
that you're familiar with
the shuttle's controls
and Dr. Reyga's
modifications.
I am an accomplished pilot.
It will be no problem.
Well,
what do you think?
I am gratified,
Dr. Jo'bril.
And there will be
no difficulty
in operating
the metaphasic controls.
The system will activate
automatically
as you approach
the star.
CRUSHER:
Well, then,
we'll proceed with
the demonstration
at 1500 hours.
We'll meet
on the Bridge.
It wasn't exactly
an enthusiastic response
to Dr. Reyga's technology,
but given the circumstances
and the scientists'
quarrelsome personalities
I was quite pleased.
I thought that went well,
didn't you?
Thanks to you, doctor.
I didn't do anything.
This is an opportunity
I would never have
had without you
and I promise you,
I'll never forget it.
Some of the scientists
still seem a little doubtful
but after the demonstration,
I'm sure they'll come around.
Well, if there's
anything I'm used to
it's skepticism.
After all,
a Ferengi scientist
is almost a
contradiction in terms.
No. Don't deny it.
I know how the Ferengi
are regarded.
I still expect
the scientific community
to be a little more open
than they seem to be.
The metaphasic shield
is a breakthrough
in technology.
Many scientists have
tried to develop it.
It's only natural that there
would be some... resistance.
You mean jealousy.
I know.
I wondered if
that might account
for Dr. T'pan's
attitude.
She's been working
on subspace shielding
technology for years
and you've beaten her
to the punch.
I'm really not interested
in competition.
All I want is
to be acknowledged--
respected
as a scientist.
This invention
will finally do that.
CRUSHER:
I figured
the hard part was over.
I'd stepped out on a limb,
and it hadn't broken.
Not bad for my first venture
into scientific diplomacy.
Captain, the shuttle
has been launched.
On screen.
Open a channel.
I am one million kilometers
from the star's corona.
Proceeding
at 3/4 impulse.
I should reach it in
approximately three minutes.
The metaphasic shielding
has begun to form.
DATA:
External temperature
is 0.9 million Kelvins
and rising.
Radiation levels are
nearing 10,000 rads.
That should have no effect
on the shuttle cabin.
That's right.
Temperature in the cabin
is 21 degrees Celsius
and the radiation
levels are normal.
Wait. I'm reading elevated
neutrino levels in the cabin.
Those are from
the subspace field
that's encapsulating
the shuttle.
The levels are well within
acceptable parameters.
Outside temperature
is rising rapidly--
1.7 million Kelvins.
CRUSHER:
Temperature is
still 21 degrees
and the shield
is holding.
350,000 kilometers
and closing.
This is incredible.
I am actually
flying into a star.
Congratulations, doctor.
This is an amazing
achievement.
Radiation levels
outside the shuttle
are nearing 14,000 rads.
The temperature
inside the cabin
is still normal.
I am now fully engulfed
in the corona.
It's astonishing.
You see, doctors.
Metaphasic shielding
is a reality.
Dr. Jo'bril,
can you give us
an estimate of
the plasma turbulence?
( beeping )
( breathing heavily )
Dr. Jo'bril.
Something's wrong.
What's going on,
Mr. Data?
Sensors indicate
an increased level
of baryon particles
in the cabin.
REYGA:
No.
That's not possible.
Dr. Jo'bril,
can you hear me?
Please respond.
( gasping )
Baryon levels are
continuing to rise, sir.
( gasping )
REYGA:
I don't understand it.
This shouldn't be
happening.
Mr. Worf, can you
beam him out of there?
The solar radiation
is interfering.
He must be at least
500,000 kilometers
from the star
before we can get
a transporter lock.
( gasping )
We're losing him.
Dr. Jo'bril, listen to me.
It is imperative
that you turn the shuttle.
Take it out
of the corona.
Do you understand me?
Pilot the shuttle
away from the star.
The shuttle is emerging
from the corona, sir.
Mr. Worf, get a lock on him
as soon as you can.
Beam him directly
to Sick Bay.
At that point, the doubts of
the others seemed justified.
I had no idea
what had gone wrong
or how seriously Dr. Jo'bril
had been injured,
but I knew this incident
could destroy Reyga's chance
to be accepted by
the scientific community.
20cc's Inaprovaline.
( labored breathing )
It's not working.
Cortical stimulators.
Now.
( raspy breathing )
Again.
( hoarsely ):
I saw...
...the sun.
( long gasp )
So that was my
first experience
as a scientific
diplomat.
A complete failure.
( sighs )
I don't understand.
No?
I mean, I've lost
patients before.
But this was different.
Mm-hmm.
You know, when you're a doctor
and you have patients
you're in control,
but when you send
somebody out on a mission
all you can do
is sit and watch.
That's what I felt...
helpless.
Anybody would.
Don't be too hard
on yourself.
You know, what you say
reminds me
of something
Jean-Luc said to me
when I was doing
the autopsy on Jo'bril.
It was probably
the most puzzling autopsy
I've ever performed,
and the most frustrating
because Jo'bril's anatomy
was unlike any
I'd encountered,
and I've run into
some unusual specimens.
How's it going?
I've never run into
a humanoid species
like this before.
His internal physiology
is baffling.
He doesn't seem to have
any discrete organs--
at least not in
the traditional sense.
Practically every system
is equally distributed
throughout the body.
Now, that kind
of physiology
should make him incredibly
resistant to any injury,
so whatever killed him
must have occurred
at the cellular level.
Do you have any idea
what it was?
No. Something
caused a massive,
system-wide failure
but I don't know what.
Were the solar radiation levels
high enough to kill him?
His exposure to the star's
radiation was minimal.
It's all very strange.
There's no apparent
cause of death.
Doctor,
here's the result
of the tissue scan
you asked for.
That's odd.
The rate of cellular
decay is extremely low.
Beverly,
the answers will come.
Maybe even minimal exposure
to the radiation
altered
the cellular physiology.
You know, you've been
at this for hours.
You might think
more clearly
if you got a good
night's sleep.
I can't sleep.
I want to find out
what killed him.
I owe that
to Dr. Reyga.
Are you doing it for
Dr. Reyga or yourself?
What do you mean?
You're the loneliest person
in the world right now.
No one can say anything,
no one can do
anything that will help,
and you think that
it will never go away
and you're right--
it won't,
but you can
get used to it.
I know it doesn't
feel like that now,
but you can.
At the time, I was too
preoccupied with my problems
to understand
what he was saying.
I wasn't thinking about
the rest of my life.
I was trying to make sense
of what had happened
and I wasn't alone.
Jo'bril's death had raised
a lot of questions.
Geordi and Data were determined
to find out what had gone wrong
and they were busy going over
every millimeter
of the shuttle--
with Dr. Reyga's help.
Run a diagnostic on
the EPS flow regulator.
The flow regulator
is functioning normally.
What about the field
emitter coil?
Has it maintained
polarity?
Yes, doctor.
The radial force
compensator?
I am unable to locate
any malfunctions.
All systems are operating
according to your
design specifications.
Did you find
anything wrong?
No. I don't
understand it.
There must be something
we've overlooked.
I found micro-crystalline
damage to the hull,
which confirms
that your shield
was breached by a burst
of baryonic radiation.
Were the levels high enough
to cause damage
to organic tissue?
I don't know.
Perhaps there was
an unexpected interaction
between the solar radiation
and the metaphasic shield.
No! That's not possible.
I anticipated
every contingency.
Then, maybe Jo'bril
ran into something
in the corona which
you didn't anticipate,
and your shield just wasn't
able to protect him from it.
My shield
was not at fault.
CRUSHER:
Reyga seemed angry,
but I knew it was because
he was so disappointed.
Everything he'd worked for,
hoped for, was slipping away
and that made what I had
to do next even harder.
I'm sure
you all understand
that, in light of
what happened,
I think it would be
inappropriate
to continue
further testing.
Perhaps if Dr. Reyga
has perfected
his metaphasic technology
we can try again.
Dr. Crusher, please,
if I could have
a little more time
to investigate,
I know I could find
what went wrong.
But that won't bring back
Jo'bril, will it?
I do not believe
the shield will ever work.
Its very concept
is flawed.
Just one more test.
Whom do you propose
we sacrifice next?
I will pilot
the shuttle myself.
I'm sorry.
As chief medical officer,
I'm responsible
for the health and safety
of all the people aboard.
I will not authorize
any further tests.
Very well.
But I will prove myself.
I couldn't help
but admire his tenacity.
He just wasn't going
to accept defeat
and I hoped
he would prove himself,
but that was the last time
I saw him alive.
We'd gone to science lab four
when the ship's sensors
registered a sizable
plasma surge there.
Look at this--
a plasma infuser.
It's completely
discharged.
The blast must have
killed him instantly.
Well, perhaps
he could not live
with the failure
of his invention
and took his own life.
Or perhaps someone
just wanted it
to look that way.
Isn't it odd that
he could hold on so
tightly to the infuser
when it was discharged?
The normal reflex would
have been to drop it.
The plasma shock could have
affected his nervous system.
He may have reacted
by gripping tighter.
I'll know for certain
when I do the autopsy.
Is your examination
complete, doctor?
For now.
Please have his body
taken to the morgue.
Very well.
I remembered his passion
and commitment
and his determination
to prove himself,
and I was sure that this man
had not taken his own life,
and if anyone could
understand that
I knew it would be
Captain Picard.
I was with him
right before he died.
He was not suicidal.
But by your own admission
Reyga was a difficult man
to understand.
Isn't it possible that he was
simply masking his feelings?
I don't think so.
He was disappointed at
the failure of his device
and certainly he was upset
at Jo'bril's death,
but I never got the sense
that he was ready to
end his own life,
and if that's true, then
someone else killed him.
Do you have
any evidence of that?
Not yet.
But when I finish the autopsy
I hope I'll have it.
Beverly...
I'm afraid there
will be no autopsy.
The family have already
been contacted.
They insist that the body
must not be touched
until they perform
the Ferengi death ritual.
But there's a question as to
the circumstances of his death.
To the family,
that's irrelevant.
Let me speak with them.
Please, believe me...
they're adamant.
We are scheduled
to rendezvous
with a Ferengi vessel
in 17 hours.
They will pick up
Reyga's body then.
I'm sorry, there
will be no autopsy.
Jean-Luc, I cannot
just drop this.
Don't you see?
There may have been
a murder.
Then you will have
to find evidence
some way other
than an autopsy.
I don't understand,
doctor.
Isn't it pretty clear
that Reyga died
from a plasma
discharge?
It won't be clear
until after an autopsy.
As far as I know,
he could have been poisoned
and someone put
the plasma infuser
in his hand
after he died.
You think
he was murdered?
I'm not discounting
that possibility.
The point is,
without a complete autopsy
there's no way of
knowing for certain.
Why won't the Ferengi
allow it?
It has to do with
their death rituals.
A body can't be violated
before it's buried.
And apparently, the family is
more concerned about ritual
than finding out the truth
about how he died.
I just can't get
the information I need
from a tricorder scan.
Suspects.
If Reyga didn't kill himself,
someone else did.
So who are
the possible suspects?
Whoever had something
to gain from his death.
And the only ones
to fit that category
are the other scientists.
I'm afraid I don't
understand, doctor.
Do you have evidence
that Reyga was murdered?
No, but I can't believe
he took his own life
and I would like to
explore any possibilities
a bit further.
What reason would
anyone have to kill him?
I was wondering
if you might have some
thoughts along that line.
I see.
You are suggesting that
I had such a motive.
If Reyga's technology
had been successful,
you might have been displaced
as the preeminent scientist
in subspace technology.
But since it
wasn't successful
it isn't logical
to conclude
that I had such
a motive, is it?
I must say I resent this,
doctor.
We have all been shocked
by recent events.
I don't see there's
anything to gain
by dragging us through
these insinuations.
I'm just trying
to uncover the truth
and I need your help
to do it.
Have you seen
or heard anything
that might suggest that
someone else had a motive?
We are trying to forget
the unpleasantness
of these past
several days--
not have them
stirred up again.
I find it disturbing
that you would try to
foster suspicions among us.
Forgive me.
I don't mean
to upset you,
but have you noticed
anything unusual?
I find your question
distasteful.
Is there something
you're not telling me?
I'm sure it's nothing.
I was
in the storage room
of the science
laboratory yesterday.
Kurak was working
in the lab.
Reyga came in, and...
they got into
an... an argument.
About what?
I don't know.
I couldn't hear
anything clearly, and...
until they started to
shout at one another.
Then I heard Kurak
say that Reyga
had insulted her honor
and no Klingon
would stand for that.
I do not believe
she killed him.
These were words spoken
in the heat of anger.
Kurak is volatile...
passionate...
but not a killer.
And, doctor,
neither are we.
Thank you.
I knew he might be right
about Kurak.
Klingons make threats
as a matter of course.
On the other hand,
sometimes they follow through.
That looks like
one of Dr. Reyga's
shield configurations.
Yes.
Personal research.
Even though
this technology failed?
No one has denied there is
potential in the idea.
Which you're now free
to develop.
Are you accusing me
of something?
No.
But I want to know
why you threatened Dr. Reyga.
I warned Dr. Reyga
that if he persisted
in his slander
he would pay the price.
What was his accusation?
I will not repeat
his lies.
Were they lies?
Be careful, doctor.
Insulting the honor
of a Klingon can be
extremely dangerous.
Did Reyga
make that mistake?
( grunts )
I have heard enough
of your accusations!
Now I will have
your silence!
( panting )
Well, you're going
to have to throw me
a lot harder than that
if you want to get it.
Now...
what did he
accuse you of?
Sabotage.
Sabotage of
the metaphasic shield?
Was that
why it failed?
How would I know?!
Did you sabotage
the project?
No.
I did not.
Good-bye, doctor.
Kurak refused
to say anything more.
I wasn't sure if her silence
was motivated by guilt
or just Klingon pride.
I was beginning to find out
that investigating a murder
was a little more perilous
than I'd thought.
And for everything
I'd been through,
I didn't have any more insight
than I did before I started.
Which brought me back
to Reyga's body,
because the more
I thought about it
the more it seemed that
the answers had to be there.
DNA traces...
tissue anomalies...
a wealth of forensic clues
that could shed some light
on the mystery.
So, I made the decision.
( sighs )
Come.
Beverly.
Jean-Luc, I want to
tell you something
that you need to know
but you're not
going to like it.
I did an autopsy
on Dr. Reyga.
What did you find?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
I know I shouldn't
have done it.
You most certainly
should not.
I made it clear to you that
the family would not allow it.
Not only have you
disobeyed my orders
but you've interfered
in the burial rituals
of another culture.
You've put both of us
in a very difficult position.
The family will have
to be notified.
I don't doubt that
they will react strongly.
( sighs )
And if the Ferengi government
becomes involved--
as I'm certain
they will--
this could have
very significant repercussions.
I'm not sure how much
I can protect you.
You don't have to,
Jean-Luc.
I knew what I was doing
and I'm prepared to
accept the consequences.
I could tell that he was
terribly disappointed in me
and that was almost
the hardest part of all.
So that's the story.
That's how I ended
my career.
Backhand volley.
What?
That's how I did it.
Geordi kept hitting
to my backhand at the net.
Guinan, two people
have died on this ship--
two lives
that ended horribly--
and you're worried
about your tennis game?
Are you upset?
I don't know--
you tell me.
You're supposed
to be wise.
Well, if you are upset,
why are you
moping around here?
Why don't you do
something about it?
I've done everything
I could think of.
It got me fired.
Do you think Dr. Reyga
killed himself?
No.
Do you think there's
a murderer on board?
Yes.
Then why are you
still sitting here?
Don't you get it?
If I start digging
around again...
You could be
relieved of duty.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
personal, Stardate 46830.1.
I'll be leaving
the ship tomorrow
to attend the board
of inquiry.
That means I have
less than 24 hours
to get to the bottom
of this mystery.
What are you doing,
Data?
I am running
additional diagnostics
to make certain there was
no permanent radiation damage
to the shuttlecraft hull.
You've studied Dr.
Reyga's shield system.
Do you think it could
have been sabotaged?
There was no evidence
to support sabotage.
Just consider
the possibility.
The system interlocks prevent
access to the circuitry
unless the shield emitter
is active.
Any attempt
to sabotage the device
would have to be made
while the shield
is in operation.
The only time
the shield was active
was during Jo'bril's
test flight.
That is correct.
It seems unlikely that Jo'bril
would perform sabotage
which would result
in his own death.
I agree.
Would it be possible
to sabotage the shuttle
by remote
during the flight?
A phased ionic pulse
beamed directly
into the metaphasic
projection matrix
would result in a temporary
system malfunction.
Where on the Enterprise
could you generate
a phased ionic pulse?
Such a pulse could be initiated
from the lateral sensor array,
Science Labs
One, Four and 16,
or any of the Bridge
science stations.
Let's assume
for the moment
that someone did send out
a phased ionic pulse.
What would have happened
inside the shuttle?
A tetryon field would be
formed briefly in the cabin,
temporarily disrupting
the metaphasic shield.
A tetryon field.
If Jo'bril was exposed
to a tetryon field
it might have left
residual traces
in his tissue.
Thanks, Data.
Beverly?
Yes?
We've arranged
for the shuttle
to take you
to Starbase 23.
You can leave the ship
at 0700 hours tomorrow.
Thank you.
About everything that's
going on, I'm sorry.
I'm sure it will
all work out.
Yes, of course.
You know the inquiry
is just a formality,
and Captain Picard
will do everything
he can for you.
I'm sure that'll help.
But if you do anything
foolish before that inquiry
it's not going
to look good for you.
I don't know
what you mean.
I think you do know
what I mean.
The best thing
for you to do right now
is to go to your quarters
and read a good book.
If you do anything to
make the situation worse
it's going to be that
much harder on you.
Thank you, Commander.
Your concern is noted.
Beverly, I'm saying this
to you as a friend.
Yes, Will, I know,
but, as a friend,
please try to understand.
I can't quit now
and I don't want you to
become involved in this.
Computer, access
ship's medical logs
and download
current autopsy files.
COMPUTER:
Autopsy files are restricted to
active medical personnel only.
Access denied.
Damn.
Dr. Crusher?
What do you need
the autopsy files for?
Don't worry, I know
I'm not supposed to be here.
I'll go.
Computer...
access autopsy files.
I assume you'll need the files
on Dr. Reyga and Jo'bril.
Alyssa...
I can see how important
this is to you.
I don't want you
to get involved in this.
Is that an order,
doctor?
Yes.
Too bad you're not
my boss anymore.
Thank you.
So what do we do now?
First, I want to review
Jo'bril's physiology records.
Then, I want to take
another look at the body
and I want to see if
there's any tetryon traces.
Let's do it.
We need to run a tissue scan
at the molecular level.
Calibrate the scanner
to pick up
tetryon particles.
Yes, doctor.
Recalibration complete.
Activate the scan.
Nothing.
Let's do it again.
Use the enhanced-
resolution mode
to boost
the sensitivity.
There's something
in the subdermal tissue.
Narrow the scan field.
Tetryon traces.
Someone did sabotage
the shield.
That's a possibility,
but this is very
circumstantial evidence.
There's only one way
to know for certain.
Captain.
I'm concerned
about Beverly.
I've tried several
times to talk to her
but she's been
avoiding me.
I'm not surprised.
This entire
experience has been...
DATA:
Captain.
An unscheduled launch
is taking place
in shuttle bay two.
No idea.
No one's filed
a flight plan.
On screen.
RIKER:
That's the Justman--
the shuttle
Reyga modified.
Open a hailing frequency.
Dr. Crusher, what do you
think you're doing?
Testing a theory, Captain.
A theory?
I think Dr. Reyga's
shield does work.
Return to the ship
immediately.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Worf, override
the shuttle's computer.
Return it
to the shuttle bay.
Aye, sir.
Sir, she has isolated
her navigational control.
It will not be possible to
establish remote operation.
Get a tractor beam on her.
WORF:
I cannot establish a lock.
She is too close
to the star.
Solar interference
is too high.
Mr. Data,
what is her heading?
Bearing 271 mark 4, sir.
She is headed
into the sun's corona.
Computer, begin monitoring
external temperature.
COMPUTER:
External temperature,
0.8 million Kelvins
and rising.
Beverly, what do you
hope to accomplish?
I think Dr. Reyga was
right about his shield.
The only reason it failed
is because it was sabotaged
and I'm going to prove it.
But you can't be
certain of that.
You're betting your life
on a hypothesis.
I'm not wrong.
COMPUTER:
External temperature
1.9 million Kelvins.
Sir, the shuttle
is entering the corona.
Beverly,
what's happening?
I'm all right.
Computer, shield status.
COMPUTER:
Metaphasic shield holding.
All systems within normal
operating parameters.
Congratulations,
Dr. Reyga.
You did it.
Captain, I want you
to post security guards
around the three
visiting scientists.
One of them has
to be responsible
for sabotaging
the first test.
I think if we...
( console beeping )
Sir, we have lost contact.
Crusher to Enterprise.
I've lost you.
Come in.
CRUSHER:
Justman to Enterprise.
Come in.
Enterprise, do you hear me?
They cannot hear you.
I have severed
communications.
How can you be alive?
I'd think
after your autopsy on me
you'd know
the answer to that.
The slow rate
of cellular decay.
It is a natural result
of physiostasis.
Takarans can control
their physiology
at a cellular level.
We can create
the appearance of death.
In the morgue, you were
conscious the whole time.
You heard everything
we said.
You knew everything
we were going to do.
Move away.
What are you doing?
I'm sending out
a transient subspace signal.
It will obscure the shuttle
from the Enterprise sensors
and they will interpret it
as a warp engine breach.
They will believe that
you have been destroyed.
I'd like
to thank you, doctor.
For what?
All I wanted to do
was discredit Reyga
so that no one would pursue
his technology except me,
but you have given me more
than I could have hoped.
Now I can take
the prototype itself
back to Takara,
where I will develop it
into a weapon.
All I have to do
is wait here
until the Enterprise
is convinced
you are dead
and leaves.
( groaning )
Captain, there is
no indication of debris.
However, the subspace signal
indicates a warp engine breach.
All right.
Begin a phase-one search,
starting with
the shuttlecraft's
last known coordinates.
Plot a proximity course
toward the star...
Sir, we are picking
up an object
emerging
from the corona.
Crusher to Enterprise.
I'm all right.
Returning to the ship,
and I finally have the answers
I've been looking for.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
Stardate 46831.2.
I have been reinstated
and I will be resuming
my duties shortly.
In the meantime, I have a
personal matter to attend to.
Hi, Guinan.
Hello. Ooh...
somebody's birthday?
Not unless it's yours--
it's for you.
For me?
What's the occasion?
It's a thank-you
for giving me
a good kick in the butt.
Oh, now, I didn't...
Now, I did some research.
This is the latest design,
state-of-the-art.
It is specifically designed
to cushion all vibrations,
so you will never have tennis
elbow again.
Thank you, doctor.
This looks like
a great racket
but, uh...
I don't play tennis.
Never have.