Good morning,
Commander.
Data.
Interesting night?
I found it extremely
interesting.
The lateral
sensor arrays
ran three separate
spectral analyses
on the Alawanir Nebula
on three distinct
frequencies.
I'm sorry I missed it.
I will have the report
sent to you, sir.
We are still on course
for the Gariman Sector.
Our speed is warp six.
ETA: 1300 hours.
Sick bay reported
one minor injury
in the Exobiology
Department at 0420 hours.
Very well.
Isn't Lieutenant Worf scheduled
to replace Ensign Torigan?
Yes, sir.
I was not informed
of any change
in the duty roster.
He's never late.
Riker to Lieutenant Worf.
Computer,
locate Lieutenant Worf.
COMPUTER:
Lieutenant Worf
is in his quarters.
Something's wrong.
Mr. Data, you have the bridge.
Security team, meet me on
deck seven, section 25-Baker.
CREW MEMBER:
Aye, sir.
( beeping )
Computer,
override security lock
on this door.
Authorization:
Riker-Alpha-six-zero.
WORF:
Torva... luk... do...
shell.
Torva...
Worf...
what the hell
are you doing?
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Captain...
On your feet, Lieutenant.
Sir.
Mr. Worf, your personal affairs
are strictly your own concern
until they interfere
with the operation of this ship.
You have now crossed that line.
As your captain, I want to know
exactly what is going on.
It is difficult
to explain.
Try.
Ever since I returned
from the Carraya System,
I have felt... empty.
Does this have something to do
with the Klingons you rescued
from Carraya IV?
They were young.
They knew nothing
of their heritage.
So while I was there,
I tried to teach them--
teach them about
their people,
their culture.
I told them our
ancient stories,
instructed them
in our customs,
explained
our beliefs.
And then I told them
about Kahless--
how he had united our people
long ago,
how he gave us
strength and honor,
and how he promised
to return one day
and lead us again.
Is that what you're
doing here?
Trying to recapture
those feelings?
Yes.
I was trying to summon
a vision of Kahless.
It's a pity that you
didn't try the holodeck
instead of setting fire
to your quarters.
Using the holodeck
would not have
been appropriate.
Everything
had to be real
if Kahless
were to appear.
But all this...
is for nothing.
He did not come to me.
I gave Toq and the others
a belief in sto-vo-kor,
the life which lies
beyond this life
where Kahless awaits us.
When I saw the power
of their beliefs,
I began to question
the strength of my own,
and I found it...
wanting.
Have you lost your faith
in sto-vo-kor?
To lose something
one must first
possess it.
I am not sure I ever
had a true belief.
But I should not have
allowed it to interfere
with my duties.
My behavior has been--
Inexcusable.
And understandable.
It may be
that what you are looking for
cannot be found
here on the Enterprise.
Perhaps you need
to immerse yourself
in Klingon beliefs
in order to discover
if they can hold
any truths for you.
( sighs )
Is there...
something you can do?
Is there somewhere you could go
to explore your faith
more fully?
Boreth.
The followers of Kahless
await his return there.
To Klingons, there is
no more sacred place.
Mmm. And Boreth is only 12 days
from here by shuttle.
As of this moment, Mr. Worf,
you are on leave.
Thank you, sir.
But when you set foot
on this ship again,
I expect you
to perform your duties
like a Starfleet officer.
Yes, sir.
And, Mr. Worf...
I hope you find
what you're looking for.
Thank you, sir.
( voices chanting quietly ):
Torva... luk... do... shell.
Torva... luk...
do... shell.
Torva... luk... do... shell.
Torva... luk...
do... shell.
Torva... luk... do...
Kahless!
I see Kahless!
He is standing
before me with a sword.
He wants something.
Me.
He wants me.
He wants me
to go with him!
It is a powerful vision
you have had, Divok.
Kahless wants you to join him
in sto-vo-kor.
You're only 19,
and yet your place
among the honored dead
is already secure.
Take him back
to his chamber.
Let him sleep.
You're leaving us?
It has been ten
days, Koroth.
I have had no visions.
I have received no insight.
There is nothing here for me.
What is the story
of the promise, Worf?
When Kahless
had united our people
and gave them
the laws of honor,
he saw that his work was done.
So, one night, he gathered
his belongings
and departed
for the edge of the city
to say good-bye.
The people wept.
They did not
want him to go.
Then Kahless said,
"You are Klingons.
"You need no one
but yourselves.
"I will go now
to sto-vo-kor,
but I promise one day
I will return."
Then Kahless pointed
to a star in the sky
and said, "Look for me there
on that point of light."
So, here we are...
on a world circling
that distant point of light.
It has been 15 centuries
since he made that promise
and still we wait.
What are ten days
in the life of one Klingon
compared to that?
Is the son of Mogh
really so easily discouraged?
You came to us
seeking answers,
but this is a place
of questions.
Open your heart
to Kahless.
Ask him your questions,
let him speak to you
with your mind unclouded
by doubt or hesitation.
Only then can you find
what you are looking for.
If you cannot do that,
then perhaps you should
return to your starship.
( door opens, closes )
...Luk... do... shell.
Torva... luk...
do... shell.
I see Kahless.
( gasps )
You are real.
I am Kahless,
and I have returned.
What are you doing?
Who are you?
It is Kahless.
I have returned.
You doubt me.
Who here knows the story
of how this sword
was forged?
No one knows.
It is not written
in the sacred texts.
I went into the mountains,
all the way to the volcano
at Kri'stak.
There I cut off
a lock of my hair
and thrust it
into the river of molten rock
that poured
from the summit.
The hair
began to burn.
Then I plunged it
into the Lake of Lusor
and twisted it
into this sword.
And after I used it
to kill Molor,
I gave it a name...
Bat'leth--
the sword of honor.
You know.
The story of the sword
is known only
to the high clerics.
It was never written down
so that if
he returned,
we could be sure
it was Kahless.
I have returned
because there is a
great need in my people.
They fight amongst themselves
in petty wars
that corrupt the glory
of the Klingon spirit.
They have lost their way...
but it is not too late.
I have returned,
and I will lead
my people again.
Vorch-doh-baghk, Kahless.
ALL:
What is it
you are doing?
I was getting my tricorder.
Tricorder?
Is it a weapon?
No. No. It is a tool.
I intended to use it
to see if...
To see if I was real.
Proceed.
Use your tricorder.
( laughing )
Well?
You are Klingon.
What else could I be?
There are many possibilities--
a shape-shifter,
a holographic projection.
So, you are
a skeptic, Worf.
I like that.
How do you know
my name?
We have met before.
I appeared to you in a vision
in the caves of No'mat.
You were just
a child then.
I told you that you
would do something
that no Klingon
had ever done before.
You still do not believe
it is me do you, Worf?
I want to believe.
That is a beginning.
( door opens, closes )
Gowron is the leader
of the council.
He commands
the entire defense force.
If he chooses
to oppose you...
Do not worry.
We are on the threshold
of a new era for our people.
Klingons from all
over the empire
will flock
to my banner.
And yet...
something still weighs heavy
on the brow of the son of Mogh.
Are you
contemplating
yet another
question for me?
After three days,
I am beginning to wonder
if you know
how to do anything else.
Questions are
the beginning of wisdom,
the mark of a true warrior.
Do not forget that a leader
need not answer questions
of those he leads.
It is enough
that he says to do a thing
and they will do it.
If he says to run,
they run.
If he says to fight,
they fight.
If he says to die...
they die.
If the commander
is worthy of that trust.
( speaking Klingon )
( grunting )
( laughing )
What is wrong?
Is there only anger
and bloodlust in your souls?
Is that all that is left
in the Klingon heart?
We do not fight
merely to spill blood,
but to enrich
the spirit.
Look at us--
two warriors
locked in battle,
fighting for honor!
How can you not sing
for all to hear?
"We are Klingons!"
( laughing )
Yes.
Let it out.
Let the joy in your
heart be heard.
We are Klingon!
We are Klingon.
( laughing )
ALL:
We are Klingons!
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46852.2.
The Enterprise is to proceed
directly to the planet Boreth
to take aboard
a very unusual guest.
Did you take any other
tricorder readings--
an anatomical profile
or a neurophysiology scan?
No.
It's going to be
very difficult
to eliminate any possibilities
at this point.
He may be a coalescent
being taking Klingon form,
or a bioreplicant,
or even a Klingon who has
been surgically altered
to look like Kahless.
WORF:
There is another
possibility.
He could be the real Kahless.
He may have actually
returned as he promised.
The appearance of Kahless
in the lava caves
is consistent
with the stories
found in the Klingon
sacred texts.
Worf, no offense,
but I have trouble believing
that the man that I escorted
from deck eight is supernatural.
I did not say that he is.
I merely think
we should not completely
reject the possibility.
Look, we have no reason
to rule out anything.
We are not ordered
to investigate
the origins of our guest,
nor to tell anyone
what they should believe.
We are simply to transport
Kahless to the homeworld.
And while he's here with us,
he will be treated
as an honored guest.
Lieutenant.
May I ask a question?
In the absence
of empirical data,
how will you determine
whether or not
this is the real Kahless?
It is not an
empirical matter.
It is a matter of... faith.
Faith.
Then you do believe
Kahless may have
supernatural attributes.
As an android,
I am unable to accept
that which cannot be proven
through rational means.
I would appreciate hearing
your insights on this matter.
Perhaps some other time,
Commander.
I... do not believe
I can provide much...
insight
at this moment.
Welcome aboard, Gowron.
Where is he, Picard?
I assume that you
are referring to Kahless.
I am referring
to the filthy pahtak
who is using his name.
Well, the person
in question
is in his quarters
at the moment.
What have you learned
about him so far?
What kind of medical
analysis have you made?
Do you have any theories
about his true origin?
We haven't done any analysis.
What kind of fools
do you have working
for you, Picard?
The impostor's been aboard
for nearly a day.
If you had wanted
to run tests on Kahless,
you should have sent
a Klingon ship for him.
And have him begin spreading
his poisonous lies
through a ship
of loyal Klingons? Never.
If he really is an impostor,
then you have
nothing to worry about.
Kahless has been dead
for 1,000 years,
but the idea of Kahless
is still alive.
Have you ever fought
an idea, Picard?
It has no weapon
to destroy,
no body to kill.
The idea of Kahless' return
must be stopped here, now,
or it will travel through
the empire like a wave
and leave nothing
but destruction behind.
So, Gowron has come on board
in order to test your claim.
Gowron knows that
his days are nearly over.
Now he comes crawling aboard
with some kind of test.
We do not have to prove
anything to Gowron.
What is this test?
He has brought a knife
with him--
a knife that is supposed
to be stained
with the blood of Kahless.
Gowron has brought
the knife of Kirom?
No one is permitted
to remove it
from the sacred vault.
Gowron does not care
about what is sacred.
He wants to run
a genetic analysis
on a sample of the blood,
and on you.
That should tell us
if there is a biological match.
Now, if you agree
to the test,
I will make the Enterprise
facilities available
to ensure that it is
conducted impartially.
Perhaps it is time
to settle the doubts
of those who still
do not believe.
I will allow this test.
There, that should do it.
Computer, run
a genetic comparison
on this blood sample
and the tissue
belonging to Kahless.
COMPUTER: The genetic patterns
are identical.
But how?
How can this be?
It is true.
Kahless has returned.
Ah...
I am sorry.
Our replicators
do not do justice
to Klingon warnog.
It's been so long
since I have tasted
any food or drink.
There are many things
I have forgotten.
Kahless...
May I ask you about... death...
and sto-vo-kor?
Tell me--
what awaits us
beyond this life?
I do not have
those answers.
I am merely a traveler--
someone who has journeyed
back and forth
between this world
and the next.
While I am in this form,
I know only
about this world.
And there is
much work for me to do
in this world.
And you will be
part of it, Worf.
Me?
It was your purity
of heart
that summoned me
back from sto-vo-kor.
And Koroth has told me
about the respect
you have earned
in the Federation
and the empire.
I want you to have
a place at my side
as we restore honor
to our people.
Let me tell you
about this new empire
we will forge.
It will be glorious!
It will be war!
( sighs )
You're not a fool, Worf.
Do you really think
that every Klingon
in the empire
will bend his knee
and grovel before this man
just because Koroth
says he is Kahless?
He is Kahless.
Your own test
proved it.
I will not hand over
the empire to Koroth
because of one test.
It is not Koroth, it is...
Of course, it is Koroth!
Open your eyes!
Koroth and the other guardians
have always opposed me.
This is nothing more
than a ploy for them
to finally seize power.
Even now, there are warriors
on my own ship
who want to see Kahless.
There are others who believe
he is an impostor.
The divisions
are already forming.
But it does not have
to be this way.
We could all join together
and welcome Kahless
as a united people.
Don't you see?
This is exactly why
they want you to join them,
because your brother
sits on the council,
and your voice carries weight
in the empire.
They want you to influence
others to follow them.
Worf...
we fought together
once, side by side,
to keep the empire
from being torn apart.
Will you stand by
and let these
impostors destroy
all that we fought
so hard to protect?
Renounce him, Worf.
Stand with me
and we can hold
the empire...
together.
You do not understand.
Kahless is our future.
Only with his help
can we revive the pure warriors
within ourselves.
Listen to him, Gowron.
Open your heart.
Hear his words.
He will restore your faith
as he has restored mine.
Give him a chance to lift
your spirit
and cleanse your heart
before you take up arms.
Koroth...
I see that not all
fools die young.
( laughing )
Kahless.
KOROTH:
Kahless, may I present Gowron,
leader
of the high council.
Kahless.
Long ago, a storm was heading
toward the city of Quin'lat.
The people sought protection
within the walls--
all except one man
who remained outside.
I went to him and asked
what he was doing.
"I am not afraid," he said.
"I will not hide my face
behind stone and mortar.
I will stand before the wind
and make it respect me."
I honored his choice
and went inside.
The next day,
the storm came
and the man was killed.
The wind does not
respect a fool.
Do not stand
before the wind, Gowron.
What was his name?
What?
If you were really there,
you should be able to tell us
the name of the man
outside the walls.
Describe him to us.
What was he wearing?
How tall was he?
What color were his eyes?!
I do not remember.
It was long ago
and in another lifetime.
What matters is I have returned
to restore faith and hope
to my people,
to lead them back
to the way of honor
and the glory
that once was theirs
and can be again.
Is that
what you oppose, Gowron?
I oppose you.
I say you are
not Kahless.
( grunts )
And I will not
bend my knee to you...
as long as I can draw breath...
or pick up a blade.
( grunts )
KOROTH:
No!
Koroth!
( grunting )
Good try, Gowron,
but not enough.
( grunts )
( Kahless laughing )
You have no joy, Gowron.
Is your heart so full
of mistrust and suspicion
that you've forgotten
what it means
to be truly Klingon?
( Gowron grunting angrily )
Kahless...
the greatest warrior
of them all.
( Gowron laughing )
Everything will
be all right.
We will say that...
that Gowron used a
dishonorable tactic
in his fight
with Kahless.
That he cheated.
That is a lie.
He did not--
We do not need
to hear any more
from the son of Mogh.
None of this would
have happened
if you had not brought
them together.
I am Kahless.
I am the strongest,
the bravest warrior.
Do not think
about what happened.
You must think of the future,
of the empire.
There is no future here,
no glorious new era
for our people.
Gowron was right.
You did not know the name
of the man who faced the storm.
You do not even know
what real warnog tastes like,
and you certainly are not
the greatest warrior of all.
Whoever you are,
you are not Kahless.
You have said enough.
Now get out!
You are using
the name of Kahless
for some twisted game.
For that alone,
you should die.
And if you do not tell me
what you have done,
I will kill you right here!
( sighs )
Problems with
your memory
are the result
of the way
you returned.
What do you mean?
We, the guardians,
have been awaiting your
return for centuries,
but we did not have
the technology
to bring you back until now.
We were able to use
an organic sample
of the first Kahless
to give you life.
The first Kahless?
A clone.
He is a clone.
What is a clone?
A being created
in a laboratory
by using genetic material
from another being.
You are a copy, a fraud!
You are not just a copy.
We gave you more than
the body of Kahless.
We found a way to imprint
specific information
in your neurosynaptic patterns.
We gave you memories,
and not just any memories.
We gave you the experiences
of Kahless
as written
in the sacred texts.
So...
I did not do any
of the things
that I remember.
I was never in the
city of Quin'lat.
I never went
to the Kri'stak
volcano.
You were not awakened
until we transported
you into the cave
and you appeared
to Worf.
Before that, you were
unconscious in a laboratory
where we accelerated
your growth,
corrected any genetic
anomalies that occurred,
gave you the wisdom
and memories that...
( chuckling )
They grew you
in a test tube
like some kind of fungus
and programmed you
like a machine.
You are twisting the truth.
You talk to me of truth.
You who have brought to life
this lie and called it Kahless.
It is not a lie.
Genetically, he is Kahless,
and he is needed
by our people.
You know better than anyone
the corruption and dishonor
that is destroying the empire.
They need him.
They do not need a false god!
How do you know
that this was not the way
the prophecy was
to be fulfilled?
Who is to say
that what we did was wrong?
I am.
I will not let this fraud
continue.
Worf!
You cannot tell Gowron of this.
Do not give me orders,
Koroth.
All right, but consider this.
If you tell Gowron
what we have told you,
it will destroy him,
and with him
the last chance
to restore hope
to our people.
It's your choice.
( Klingons chanting )
They have been sitting here
for three hours, 17 minutes.
They refused to return
to their ship
with the rest
of Gowron's men.
They insisted
upon waiting here
until they see
Kahless again.
Their faith appears
to be unaffected
by his inability
to defeat Gowron.
They still believe.
Then they are fools.
Does that mean you
no longer believe
this is the
real Kahless?
Yes.
I am curious.
Do you still think
the real Kahless
will return someday,
or has this experience
only deepened the
spiritual crisis
which originally
sent you to Boreth?
I do not know.
I understand your dilemma.
I once had what could
be considered
a crisis of the spirit.
You?
Yes.
The Starfleet officers
who first activated me
on Omicron Theta
told me I was an android,
nothing more than a
sophisticated machine
with human form.
However, I realized that
if I were simply a machine,
I could never be anything else.
I could never grow
beyond my programming.
I found that
difficult to accept,
so I chose to believe
that I was a person,
that I had the potential
to be more than a collection
of circuits and
subprocessors.
It is a belief
which I still hold.
How did you come
to your decision?
I made... a leap of faith.
The man who appeared to me
on Boreth is not Kahless.
He is a clone.
A clone?
Yes.
Did you really think
you could get away with this
kind of fraud, Koroth?
I will have you and this
abomination put to death.
It does not matter, Gowron.
You will still not be able
to stand against him.
What?
He's not real.
You just said so.
I said he was not Kahless.
But, in the minds
of our people,
he can be just as
powerful as Kahless.
Even now, two members
of your own crew
are sitting on our holodeck
waiting for him to return.
I do not care
what they think.
But they are not alone.
Like many of our people,
they need something
to believe in,
just like I did-- something
larger than themselves,
something that will give
their lives meaning.
They need Kahless.
But when they find out
the truth...
It does not matter,
Gowron.
Despite the facts,
they will still believe.
They will make
a leap of faith,
and there will be
others just like them--
not everyone, but enough
to plunge the empire
into civil war
if you oppose them.
What are you saying?
That I should just hand over
the empire?
No, that would be
unwise as well.
Then what are you
proposing, Worf?
You were right about
one thing, Koroth.
Our people are becoming
decadent and corrupt.
They need
moral leadership.
Kahless can be that leader--
as emperor.
There hasn't been an emperor
in three centuries.
The political power will remain
with the high council.
Kahless would be a figurehead.
But he will have the ability
to rally the people,
to lead by example,
to guide them
in spiritual matters.
The title is meaningless
without the power
to back it up.
Real power comes
from within the heart.
You would have the power
to mold the Klingon heart.
You could return them
to honorable ways
according to the original
teachings of Kahless
which are within you.
It would be a great challenge
if you have the
courage to accept it.
And what will we tell the people
about their new emperor?
That he appeared in a cave
or a laboratory?
We will tell them the truth.
All of the truth.
But we will tell them
that even if he is
not the real Kahless,
he is the rightful heir
to Kahless.
And if I refuse to go along
with this?
Then my brother and those
who support him on the council
will fight you,
and I will fight you,
and the empire
will fall back
into civil war.
What do you say
about this, Koroth?
What I say is unimportant.
It is acceptable.
Join with me, Gowron.
Let us usher in
this new era together.
Vorch-doh-baghk...
Kahless.
Farewell, Worf.
Good-bye.
What's wrong?
You should be proud
of what you've accomplished.
I went to Boreth
to find my faith.
For a time, I thought I had,
but my heart is empty again.
I do not know what to believe.
You doubt the real Kahless
will return one day.
You doubt that he is still
waiting for you in sto-vo-kor.
Kahless left us, all of us,
a powerful legacy,
a way of thinking and acting
that makes us Klingon.
If his words hold wisdom
and his philosophy
is honorable,
what does it matter
if he returns?
What is important is that
we follow his teachings.
Perhaps the words
are more important
than the man.
Qapla', son of Mogh.
Qapla', Kahless.