Captain's Log,
Stardate 46915.2.
The Enterprise
is orbiting Nervala IV
waiting for an opportunity
to retrieve scientific data
left there
by Starfleet researchers
when they were forced
to evacuate eight years ago.
( jazz combo playing
"I Remember You" )
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Any requests tonight?
"Night Bird."
Any requests?
Ladies and gentlemen
"Night Bird."
One, two, three...
( up-tempo jazz intro )
What was that all about?
Will's been trying
to get this piece right
for ten years.
He's never made it
through the solo.
Here it comes.
Data to Commander Riker.
Go ahead.
Commander,
you are needed on the bridge.
On my way.
Saved by the bell.
You wanted to see me,
Mr. Data?
Yes, sir. It appears
we will be able
to transport
to the surface
sooner than
anticipated.
Is the planet's
distortion field
re-phasing sooner
than you predicted?
No, sir. Using
the Potemkin's transport logs
from the original evacuation,
Commander La Forge and I
were able
to modify the transporters.
So we can beam out through
a higher distortion field.
The transporters are
considerably more efficient
than those used on
the Potemkin eight years ago.
It's a good thing.
I almost didn't make it off
the surface.
When can we
get started?
97 minutes, sir.
How long will
the transport window be open?
26 minutes.
After that, the distortion
field will re-phase.
That doesn't give us much time
to retrieve the database.
The planet's proximity
to its sun will create
two additional
transport windows
in the next three days.
Let's hope
that's enough.
It will have
to be, sir.
The next transport window
will not occur
for another eight years
when the planet's orbit
will bring it close enough
to the sun to de-phase
the distortion field.
Okay, notify the away team
we'll be going in
ahead of schedule.
I'll tell the captain.
Aye, sir.
( beeping )
This is different
than I remember.
This place was a mess
when we left.
Commander...
RIKER:
Someone was here.
A ship could
have been caught
in the distortion field
and crashed.
The survivors may have
taken refuge here.
Commander,
someone is approaching.
Humanoid.
40 meters due east
and closing.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Who are you?
I'm Commander
William Riker
from the federation
starship Enterprise.
That's not possible.
I'm Will Riker.
May I ask
how you got here?
Eight years ago, I led a team
to evacuate this station.
What ship were you on?
The Potemkin.
Why did you not return
to the Potemkin
with the others?
I was the last one out.
The distortion field
must have interfered
with the transport.
They lost
the signal lock on me.
When I tried
to contact the ship
I couldn't get through
the interference.
If you check with Starfleet
I'm sure they recorded
that I was lost on that day.
That's not
what happened.
I was the last one out
and I made it back
to the Potemkin.
You don't believe me?
It's not that
we don't believe you.
It's just hard to see how
both stories could be true.
Would you be willing to have
our doctor check you out?
Of course.
Mr. Worf, take him directly
to sick bay, and notify
the captain
once you're on board.
Let's get to work.
Worf to Enterprise.
Two to beam up.
Aye, sir. Stand by.
It looks like you
fractured your arm
a few years ago.
I was doing some repairs
under the station
when an earthquake hit.
Got caught
in a rock slide.
I had to set it myself.
Jean-Luc Picard.
Lieutenant Will Riker.
I hope you understand I'll
need to verify your claim.
Yes, sir.
CRUSHER:
Genetically
he is indistinguishable
from Commander Riker.
Could there be some sort
of cloning involved here?
I don't think so.
There's
no genetic drift.
But it's not conclusive.
That's why I compared
their brain scans.
Brain organization
patterns
are as unique
as fingerprints.
Except for minor,
minor differences
theirs are identical.
But can't brain patterns
be cloned?
No. They're determined
by experience--
mostly from
early childhood.
How can two grown men
share the same childhood
experiences?
It just doesn't
make any sense.
I am Will Riker.
I don't know
who or what made it back
to the Potemkin that day,
but it wasn't me.
Lieutenant, our
chief engineer is checking
the transporter logs
of the Potemkin.
Perhaps that will shed
some light on the matter.
Don't worry.
We will get
to the bottom of this,
and in the meantime
you'll be taken
to your quarters.
Try and make yourself
as comfortable as possible.
I will.
The replicators
on the station
haven't worked
for a long time.
It's been a while
since I've had a decent meal.
Doctor.
Apparently, there was
a massive energy surge
in the distortion field
around the planet
just at the moment
you tried to beam out.
The transporter chief
tried to compensate
by initiating
a second containment beam.
Hmm, an interesting
approach.
He must have
been planning
to reintegrate
the two patterns
in the transport
buffer.
Actually, it wasn't
really necessary.
Commander Riker's pattern
maintained its integrity
with just
the one containment beam.
He made it back to the ship
just fine.
What happened
to the second beam?
The transporter chief
shut it down
but somehow, it was reflected
back to the surface.
And another William Riker
materialized there.
How was the
second pattern
able to maintain
its integrity?
The containment beam
must have had
the exact same
phase differential
as the distortion field.
Which of them is real?
LA FORGE:
Well, that's the thing. Both.
You were both materialized
from a complete pattern.
CRUSHER:
Up until
that moment
you were the same person.
PICARD:
But, of course, as you
and Lieutenant Riker
have lived
very different lives
for the past eight years
you are now
very different people.
I suppose
it's a little like
meeting someone's twin.
But no matter how strange
it may seem to us, we now have
two Will Rikers
on board, and as
Lieutenant Riker
will be with us
for several days
I think we should
do everything we
can to make him
comfortable and welcome.
RIKER:
We still have
the problem
of retrieving
the database.
The computer on the station's
not completely operational.
DATA:
Many of
its components
have been removed.
Apparently,
Lieutenant Riker used them
to keep the station's
radiation shield operational.
Can it be repaired
at least enough
to access the database?
Without knowing what he did,
that'll be tough.
Perhaps he can help us.
He was alone down there
for a long time.
I'm hesitant
to let him go back
until he's been
evaluated.
I'll talk to him.
Thank you, Counselor.
( door chimes )
Come in.
( door opens )
TROI:
Hello, Will.
Ah...
Imzadi...
Will...
I never thought
I'd see you again.
We need to talk.
You're on board
because of him.
No.
Commander Riker and I
are friends...
close friends
but nothing more.
Why don't we sit down.
Do you remember
the last time
we saw each other?
Like yesterday.
The Janaran Falls
on Betazed.
It was the day before
you started your tour
on the Potemkin.
And we were going
to meet on Risa
six weeks later.
We never did.
I know.
No...
what I mean is...
Commander Riker
and I never did.
You see, he earned
a promotion very quickly.
I know that, too.
"For exceptional valor
"during the evacuation
of the research station
on Nervala IV."
I've been looking
at his service record.
He chose to make
his career a priority.
There wasn't much time
for anything else.
We kept in touch,
but we didn't
see each other again
until we were
both posted
to the Enterprise
two years later.
By then, our feelings
for each other had changed.
We've served together
for six years...
but things never went back
to the way they used to be.
I had a lot of time
on my hands
when I was down
on that station.
There were days
that I was so lonely
I thought I might
lose my mind.
Do you know
how I made it through?
I thought if I hung on
for one more day,
they'd rescue me
and maybe
I'd see you again.
I guess things
don't always work out
the way you expect
them to.
I know this isn't
what you were hoping for
but that doesn't mean
you can't make a future
for yourself.
Thanks.
Captain Picard
wanted me to find out
if you'd be willing
to help us retrieve
the station's database.
I reconfigured that computer
so many times
they probably can't
make head or tails of it.
I'd be happy to help.
Do you feel
up to it?
Absolutely.
Good. I'll tell
the captain.
Well...
I have to go.
Deanna...
I know it's been a long time
since we've been together
and I know your feelings
have changed.
Mine haven't.
I can't just give up.
I'd like to be
with you again.
Good night, Will.
Phase distortion is dropping.
The next transport window
opens in 42 seconds.
How long will we have,
Lieutenant?
36 minutes, sir.
We are losing time.
Lieutenant Riker should be here.
Computer,
locate Lieutenant...
Cancel inquiry.
You were supposed to report here
at 0800 hours.
I'm sorry. I was...
I guess it's been a while
since you've had
to punch a clock.
Let's go.
Energize.
I shut down most
of the consoles
to save power.
I rerouted just
about everything
through here.
Check out
the primary EPS system.
See if you can get some power
to the rest of these consoles.
I shunted the database
to the main core
underneath the station.
Can we access it
from here?
Well, there's been a lot of
seismic activity
over the years.
If the servo-links were
damaged, we may not
be able to.
I'll try to tap
into the command pathways.
You see if you can access
and disable the file server.
( beeping )
You know,
I've been thinking
we should probably let Dad
know what happened.
I'm sure
he'd be thrilled
to know there are
two of us now.
Actually, he and I have been
able to patch a few things up.
Well, I've been
able to get by
for a long time
without seeing him.
I'm not about to
start now.
What made you
contact him?
I didn't.
He came on board
the Enterprise
to brief me
when I was offered the Aries.
What did he say when you
turned down your own command?
He couldn't understand
why I did it.
For once, he and I
agree on something.
The primary EPS coupling
is fused.
The entire unit will
have to be replaced.
I've accessed
the command pathways.
The interlink relays
are functioning now.
Let's see if
that did the trick.
( beeping )
No. It's not working.
The servo-link
must be damaged.
We're going to have to go
under the station--
access the core directly.
We have less than
three minutes left.
Well, I'll stay here.
I'll be finished by the time
the third window opens.
It's too dangerous.
Our scans show the caverns
are unstable.
I've been down there
dozens of times.
I know my way around.
We'll come back during
the third window.
We'll bring a
new EPS coupling.
We'll try to access the core
from another console up here.
Riker to Enterprise.
La Forge here.
We're ready
to beam out.
You go ahead.
I'll be finished
by the time you get back.
Hold it!
I gave you an order,
Lieutenant!
Computer.
Valerian root tea, hot.
"Meet me in transporter
room three at 1900 hours.
It's important."
"It pulses unendingly
all through the night.
Seek out the crystal
that powers our flight."
Can I help you,
Counselor?
No, thank you.
"What the future holds
no one can know
but forward we look
and forward we go."
Hmm.
Janaran Falls.
I remember.
Where did you
get this?
I made it a couple
of years ago
down on the station.
You made this?
Well, you should have seen
the first two.
It took a while
to get a fine enough beam
out of the phaser.
Oh, it's lovely.
Thank you.
Can you stay
and talk for a while?
Mm-hmm.
I wanted to remember
our last night together.
So, um...
how does it feel
being with people again?
Great.
Strange.
For a long time
I did whatever I wanted
whenever I wanted.
It's been hard getting used
to taking orders again.
I can imagine.
But I guess I'll have
to get used to it
if I want to get
my career going again.
Is that what
you've decided to do?
Remember, I'm the one
who wanted to make captain
by the time he was 35.
I'm a little
behind schedule.
I'll admit that.
It's good you don't
feel set back.
I do.
Things are
a little more complicated
than I had planned...
but there's nothing
going to stand in the way
of my getting
what I want.
There you go.
Thanks.
You don't know how many times
I thought about you...
about us.
For weeks
after the evacuation
I kept thinking
they'd find a way
through the distortion field
and come back for me.
I even thought...
we'd meet on Risa
like we planned.
But days went by
and nobody came,
and then I realized why.
They thought
that I had been killed
in the beam-out.
No one came down
because they thought
there was no one
to come down for.
So I figured that they'd had
a memorial service for me.
Somehow that made me
feel better.
I can understand that.
You were there.
All dressed in black.
Very flattering on you
by the way.
I'm sure I looked terrible
with my eyes all red
and swollen from crying.
Sometimes...
I would look up
into the sky and I'd think
if I tried hard enough
I could make you
feel my presence
that if I could let you know
that I was alive
maybe you'd
wait for me.
I know it-it sounds...
crazy
but there were times
when I could have sw...
What am I talking about?
The other day
when I told you
about how Commander Riker
and I
didn't meet
on Risa...
what I didn't say was
how disappointed I was.
You didn't have to.
I knew.
I started to hear from
him less and less.
I knew his career was taking
him away from me, but...
I didn't want
to believe it was over.
I spent a lot of time
thinking about him...
wondering where he was,
what he was doing.
Sometimes I'd look
into the sky
and imagine
that he knew...
and that somehow
he could sense me
thinking about him.
So, who knows?
Maybe one night
we were looking up
at the same star, and...
you were thinking
about me.
And in a way...
I was thinking
about you.
( door chiming )
Come.
You wanted to
see me, sir?
Yes, Number One.
Come in.
Lieutenant Riker
has been to see me
to talk about
the away mission.
He believes that
the only way
to retrieve
the database
is by directly accessing
the main core
underneath
the station.
The seismic activity makes
those caverns very unstable.
In my opinion,
it's too risky.
He said that he was
down there recently.
He seemed confident that
it could be done safely.
There's a good chance
we will be able
to retrieve the database
from one of the consoles
inside the station.
But if it doesn't work
we won't have another chance
for eight years.
Lieutenant Riker's plan
is more dangerous
but it does have
a better chance of succeeding.
Given the importance
of the data
I think that
it's worth the risk.
I'll look over
the schematics
and I'll draw up
a mission plan.
I'm sure that
Lieutenant Riker
will be happy
to help you with that.
I'll talk to him.
( sighs softly )
Sir.
Lieutenant.
I just met
with the captain
about your mission
recommendation.
I would appreciate it
if next time
you came to me first.
I tried talking
to you yesterday
on the station.
You wouldn't hear me out.
I heard you, Lieutenant.
I rejected your plan.
May I ask
what the captain decided?
The captain has decided to go
with your recommendation
but that's
not the point.
Isn't it?
If you think I'm
coming down on you
because the captain
overruled me
think again.
I happen to disagree
with his decision
but he is my
commanding officer
and I follow his orders.
Just so there's
no confusion
I am your commanding officer
and I expect
you to do the same.
If you can't
there's no place for you
on my away team.
Yes, sir.
There will be a meeting
in the observation lounge
at 1400 hours
to draw up a
mission plan.
We stayed in ten-forward
talking for hours.
Then what happened?
He walked me
to my quarters.
Then what happened?
Beverly.
I'm just asking.
You know it's been over
between Will and me
for a long time.
He's not Will.
He is Will, but...
you know what I mean.
It's really hard for me
to separate
my feelings for them.
Deanna, just because things
turned out the way they did
between you
and Commander Riker
doesn't mean you
shouldn't let things
between you
and Lieutenant Riker
take their own course.
I knew you'd
encourage me.
Well, I thought that's
why you brought it up.
( sighs )
( door opens and closes )
Well, I think
I'll call it a day.
( whispering ):
Beverly...
Bye.
Some form of
Tai Chi Chuan?
Klingon exercises,
actually.
Lieutenant Worf
teaches a class.
Forms are very
similar.
Do that move again.
You just did
the KoH-man-ara.
In Tai Chi Chuan
it's called
the crane block.
Now, let's try
something else.
What is that called?
Mr. Worf's
a very good teacher.
Hello, Will.
If you want to be with him
you don't have to ask
my permission.
The look in your eyes--
I recognize it.
You used to
have it for me.
We've both had relationships
with other people
but this is different.
I didn't know
how you'd feel about it.
Flattered...
sort of.
This must be
very strange for you.
Ever since
he came on board
I find myself thinking
about the choice
that you and I made.
Me, too.
Do me a favor.
Be careful.
Will, I know you and he
have had some problems.
That's not
what I'm talking about.
If he had gotten
off the planet instead of me
don't you think he would
have made the same choices
that I made?
I just don't want you
to be hurt again.
Two pair.
Full boat.
Kings over.
( groans )
I'd like to thank you both
for your very generous
contributions.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I thought you'd be alone.
Excuse me.
Why don't you join us.
DATA:
The game is
five-card draw, no limit.
Ante, please.
Lieutenant?
Three, please.
Mr. Worf?
Four.
Commander?
I'll play these.
Dealer takes two.
You control the bet,
Lieutenant.
Fifty.
Fold.
Here's your
50 and ten more.
You didn't take
any cards.
You must be
holding something.
Why not make it
a little sweeter?
No, thanks.
Playing it safe?
You in?
I will call.
Here's your ten
and it'll cost you
another 100.
I practiced in
the mirror too long
to be fooled by
that face.
You're bluffing.
Here's your hundred
and 20 more.
Dealer folds.
I thought if one thing
were clear by now
it's that you and I play
things a little differently.
Why don't we wait and see
who comes out on top.
I thought you were
willing to settle
for second, Commander.
I've never settled
for anything in my life.
I know
what I want--
I know what I've got--
and you'd be lucky to do
so well, Lieutenant.
Here's your 20.
300 more.
Now I know
you're bluffing.
Are you in or not?
Why don't we
get this over with.
I'll call your three
and I'll raise you anything
you've got left.
Well?
Take it.
You always had
the better hand...
in everything.
( door opens )
( door closes )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hi.
I'm sorry to just stop by
like this
but there's something I'd
like to talk to you about.
Captain Picard has
made some inquiries
and he managed to
get me a posting
on the Gandhi
and considering how long
I've been out of commission
it's an amazing
opportunity.
When would you leave?
In about a week.
I see.
Deanna...
after I've served
for six months
I'm eligible to bring
family aboard.
If we got married...
You said those
exact words to me
before you went to serve
on the Potemkin.
I know.
I was just
held up for a while.
But if you hadn't been
what would have happened
between us?
I wouldn't have made
the mistake of leaving you.
I know that much.
I don't know
if I can believe that.
( sighing )
It took me a long time
to get over what happened
between Commander Riker and me.
I don't know
that I want to put myself
in that position again.
I would never
hurt you, Deanna.
It's not just that.
I've worked hard to make
a life for myself
on the Enterprise.
I'm happy here.
If the situation were
different, I'd stay
but I can't...
not while he's aboard.
I know.
Are you saying
it's over?
No.
I just don't know
if I'm ready to give up
my life here.
Maybe we both
need some time.
Good night.
Captain's log, supplemental.
The third transport window
has opened
and the away team is making
their final attempt
at retrieving the database.
Once we restore
the servo-link
you can shunt the database
up to this console.
You ready, Commander Data?
You're with me,
Lieutenant.
I thought
Commander Data's expertise...
It doesn't take that
much expertise to
repair a servo-link.
You and I
can handle it.
Lieutenant, I am curious
about something.
If you met a double
of yourself
would you have difficulty
interacting with him?
I think so.
Why?
I am not easy
to get along with.
Hmm.
But Commander Riker
and Lieutenant Riker are
yet they seem to have
trouble
getting along
with each other.
I have found that humans
value their uniqueness--
that sense that
they are different
from everyone else.
The existence of a double
would preclude that feeling.
Could that be the source
of the friction?
Well, perhaps
it is more a matter
of seeing something
in your double--
something you
do not like in yourself.
This is it.
There's the core
over there.
You're waiting
for something?
Your orders, sir.
How would you like me
to get over there, sir?
You've been down here
dozens of times.
I'm sure you
know the best way.
Yes, sir, I do.
( tricorder beeping )
It's leaking
ion radiation.
Why didn't
you report this?
It wasn't here before.
This must have
just happened recently.
If we have to
repair this conduit
we won't have time
to access
that computer core.
( power humming )
Scan it now.
( beeping )
It's working.
The radiation levels
are dropping to normal.
Next time, don't
give up so easily.
Hang on.
Come on, grab on.
Come on!
Climb!
I'm being pulled in.
Let go!
One of us has
to get out of here!
Climb!
Come on!
( grunting )
( both grunting and panting )
( sighing )
( beeping )
They have restored
the servo-link to the core.
We can begin downloading
the database.
Initiating data transfer.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46920.1.
We have retrieved the database
from Nervala station
and are headed for our
rendezvous with the Gandhi.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I hear the Gandhi's going
on a terraforming mission
to the Lagana sector.
That's right.
It'll take us four months
just to get there.
I won't be joining you.
I guess I'm not surprised
to hear that.
I'm just not ready
to give up my life here.
Not yet.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
I wanted to give you something.
My quarters are
full of things
that I suppose
belong to both of us.
The least I could do
was give you this.
Thanks.
Good luck, Will.
I actually thought I might
go with the name Thomas.
Your middle name.
I guess we really
are different.
I never really
cared for that name.
Well, I sort of like it.
I guess
I better get going.
I waited a long time.
I guess I can wait
a little longer.
Take care of her.