( Crusher tsking )
Oh, you really did it
this time, Will.
I mean, this is not
just a scrape.
This is a very deep cut.
Well, I can heal it, of course
but you've got to stop
playing Parrises Squares
as if you're 21 years old.
One of these days,
you're going to fall
and break your neck
and I'm not going to be able
to heal that as easily.
I wasn't playing
Parrises Squares.
Worf's calisthenic
program.
No.
I give up.
What was it?
I was trying to feed Spot.
Data's cat?
I told him I would feed
him while he was gone.
I was putting down
the bowl of food.
The next thing I know
there's a hissing ball
of fur coming at my face.
I hate cats.
I love cats.
You know, you've just got
to know how to handle them.
Maybe you'd
like to do it.
I would be honored if I could...
WORF:
Commander Riker to the Bridge.
On my way.
Oh, by the way...
you'll need this.
Report.
We're picking up
a distress call
on long-range sensors.
It is Romulan, sir.
Romulan.
They claim they have suffered
a complete engine failure.
Power levels are dropping.
Life-support is failing.
Could be a trick.
How long before we rendezvous
with Captain Picard?
Approximately 13 hours.
Lay in a course
for the Romulan ship.
Let's put up the shields
and go to red alert.
I want to be ready
for anything.
Aye, sir.
( alarm wailing )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46944.2.
Commander Data, Mr. La Forge,
Counselor Troi and I
are en route to the Enterprise
after attending
a three-day conference
on the psychological effects
of long-term
deep-space assignments.
Computer, activate
automatic helm control.
Helm control activated.
I was just leaving the reception
when this Ktarian
walks up to me and says
( imitating ):
"Hello, Diane.
"I understand you're an empath.
"I'm a very...
sensitive man myself.
"I'm doing a thesis
on interspecies mating rituals.
Would you care to join me
in some empirical research?"
That's a very good impression
of Dr. Mizan.
How did you know?
He's notorious
but he really is an expert
on interspecies
mating practices.
Did you help him
with his research, Counselor?
Absolutely not.
I thought it was a topic
you were interested in.
How did you enjoy
the rest of the conference,
Counselor?
To be honest, I was bored.
I spent most of my time
at Professor Wagner's
phylobiology seminar.
I thought the idea
of the seminar
was that we would
all participate--
bring different points of view
to the discussion.
He gathered 200 scientists
from all over the Federation
and all he did
was put us to sleep.
I have a memory record of
the entire lecture, Counselor.
I could repeat
the portions
you missed...
No, thank you, Data.
PICARD:
Well, it was little better
at the physiognomy workshop.
Dr. Fassbinder
gave an hour-long dissertation
on the ionization effect
of warp nacelles
before he realized
that the topic was supposed
to be... psychology.
Why didn't anybody tell him?
There was no opportunity.
There was no pause.
( droning ):
He just kept talking
in one long,
incredibly unbroken sentence
moving from topic to topic
so that no one had a chance
to interrupt.
It was really quite hypnotic.
LA FORGE:
Well, I had a great time.
The warp energy symposium
was fascinating.
I actually had an opportunity
to touch a plasma field.
Really?
What was it like?
Oh, it was incredible.
I could feel the plasma
moving up my arm.
It was warm and...
Oh, and there was this amazing
tingling sensation that...
Captain?
Data.
...moved through my chest.
It was incredible.
It was like
taking a bath
in pure energy.
It was not painful?
Oh, no. I...
Counselor?
Is there
something wrong?
I'm not sure.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Well, our bio-scans check out.
There are
no physiological anomalies.
If something did happen,
it didn't leave
any biological traces.
How long did it appear
to you that we were frozen?
I don't know.
Four, maybe five seconds.
You just stopped,
and then started again.
I can't explain it.
My memory record
does not indicate a pause
or a disruption
during that time period.
My internal chronometer
and the ship's computer
are both perfectly
synchronized.
There does not appear to be
a temporal discrepancy.
Data, let's run
a ship-wide diagnostic.
Maybe we missed
something.
Let's go through
all this again.
You were sitting there.
The rest of us were here.
Describe the exact moment
when we appeared to freeze.
Well, um... Geordi was talking
about what it felt like
to touch the plasma field
and you were taking
a sip of tea.
Did you sense something
from any of us at that time--
any unusual emotion?
Not a thing.
I was empathically aware of you
right up to the moment
when you froze
and then it all stopped.
( sighs )
The last few days
have been exhausting.
Maybe it was my imagination.
There were moments
in that lecture hall
when I thought time
was standing still there, too.
Well, there is another
possibility, Counselor.
This could be nothing more
than simp...
Oh! Oh.
You all right,
Counselor?
What happened?
You were motionless
for three minutes, 11 seconds.
It appears to be
the same effect
that you described in us.
Do you remember anything?
No. One second,
I was talking to you
and the next, you were
all standing around me.
LA FORGE:
Wait a second.
This is weird.
What is it?
I had the tricorder
run a comparison
between the bio-scan
I took on you earlier
and the one
I ran just now.
In the time between
the two scans
you should have aged
23 minutes
but according to your
cellular decay levels
you've only aged
20 minutes.
How do you account
for this discrepancy?
LA FORGE:
I don't know, sir.
It's as if,
for Counselor Troi
for three minutes,
time just stopped.
Mr. Data, contact
the Enterprise.
Tell Commander Riker
to meet us at the rendezvous
point as soon as possible.
Have him scan the region
for temporal anomalies.
Aye, sir.
I'll check
the sensor logs--
see if I can
find anything.
DATA:
Captain, may I see you?
The Enterprise is not
responding to our hails.
Are we within
sensor range?
No, sir.
Increase speed
to the rendezvous coordinates.
Aye, sir.
( low rumbling )
( warning beeps )
We have an engine-failure
warning in...
Report!
The starboard nacelle
just cut out.
Attitude control
has been restored.
Full stop.
What happened?
The starboard antimatter pod
is completely drained.
The fuel reserves are empty.
Is there a
fuel containment leak?
No, sir, the containment
field is intact.
All engine systems
are operational.
The fuel is just gone.
Geordi
I believe I have an explanation.
According to the plasma
conversion sensor
the starboard engine has been
in continuous operation
for 47 days.
47 days?
Aw...
let's check that sensor.
It must be malfunctioning.
I'll check
the fuel consumption logs.
( screaming )
What happened?
My hand.
Your cells are metabolizing
at an incredible speed--
almost 50 times normal.
The pain is going away.
Your metabolism's
stabilizing.
It happened when I reached
for the bowl of fruit.
Captain, I am detecting
a temporal disturbance
intersecting
the table.
It appears that
within the disturbance
time is moving
at an accelerated rate--
approximately 50 times
faster than normal.
The disturbance
is spherical in shape.
It is extending outward
from the hull
approximately 17 meters
from the ship.
That would cover
the starboard nacelle.
No wonder it used
up all its fuel.
Check the hull integrity.
It does not appear
to be affected.
Mr. La Forge,
see if you can
move us away from
the disturbance.
Aye, sir.
Lateral thrusters on line.
Data, plot a course
away from the disturbance.
Make sure it doesn't come in
contact with our other engine.
Course plotted.
Adjust pitch to 27.3 degrees.
Set heading--
180 mark zero.
Got it.
Reversing at 15 meters
per second.
DATA:
We are clearing the phenomenon.
( alarm beeping )
All stop.
What was that?
There is another temporal
disturbance directly behind us.
Captain
I think you'd better come
take a look at this.
Yes, Mr. La Forge?
The sensors are picking up
temporal disturbances
throughout the region.
Different configurations,
different sizes--
they're everywhere.
DATA:
Within each disturbance
it appears that time is moving
at a different rate.
It's almost as if something
has shattered
the space-time continuum.
The fragmentation
effect continues
along a heading
of 270 mark 15.
That's the direction
of the Enterprise.
Can we navigate
around these fragments?
We'll have to limit
our maneuvering speed
to one-half impulse
but I think
we can do it.
Get us to the Enterprise.
These are the coordinates.
Perhaps the Enterprise
has been delayed.
I've got the long-range
sensors on maximum, sir.
There's no sign
of the Enterprise.
But I am picking up
a faint reading--
possibly metallic.
It's difficult
to tell.
The energy levels
are practically nonexistent.
Take us to it.
Aye, sir.
DATA:
The fragmentation effect
is increasing.
Slowing to one-eighth impulse.
There she is.
My God.
Mr. Data?
The Enterprise
and the warbird
both appear
to be trapped
within one
of the temporal fragments.
LA FORGE:
The fragments seem
to be converging
at about this point.
I'd say we're looking
at the center
of the temporal
disturbances.
Scan for life signs.
Sensors cannot penetrate
the subspace field.
I am unable to scan
within the vessels.
TROI:
It looks like
the Enterprise
has been damaged.
There,
on the port nacelle.
The warbird doesn't look to have
sustained any damage at all.
I wonder if the Enterprise
even had time
to get off a shot.
The Romulans
could have de-cloaked
before the Enterprise
had a chance to respond.
There's a second energy beam.
It's coming from the Enterprise
deflector array.
Do you have any idea
what that could be?
DATA:
It is impossible to tell
from a visual inspection.
However,
it appears to be focused
on the warbird's
Engineering section.
Well, we're not going to be able
to determine anything from here.
We need to get on board
the Enterprise.
That would be inadvisable, sir.
In each of the three
instances
we came into contact
with one
of the temporal fragments
we were integrated
into its time frame.
If we beamed aboard
the Enterprise
we'd be frozen in time
just like they are.
Well, we have to find some way
of staying unfrozen.
Mr. La Forge, what about
a subspace force field
like the one we used
on Devidia II?
Could something like that
protect us
from the effects
of the temporal fragment?
Possibly, but we'd need
an awfully sensitive
phase discriminator
in order to moderate
that kind of field.
The emergency transporter
armbands
contain a type-seven
phase discriminator.
It should be possible
to reconfigure
their subspace emitters.
Yeah.
Yeah, that would
certainly isolate us
from the effects of
the other time frame
but if we wanted to interact
with that environment
we'd have to
restrict the field.
It would have to be
practically skintight.
Mr. Data.
I will attempt
to narrow the field, sir.
LA FORGE:
Captain, I think
this is going to work
but... it's going
to take some time.
Well, Mr. La Forge
it would seem
that time is something
that we have plenty of.
I've channeled
all communications
through the subspace relays
in the armbands.
That way, we'll be able to be
in continual communication.
How long will the fields last?
About an hour,
maybe less.
Don't worry.
I'll be monitoring you
very carefully.
Oh.
Counselor.
I got a little dizzy
for a second.
We've created an artificial
pocket of time around you
so it's probably playing tricks
with your equilibrium.
It might take a little while
to get used to it.
You let me know if it
gets any worse.
Mm-hmm.
Beam us directly
to the Enterprise Bridge.
Aye, sir.
Energizing.
There are three Romulans
all of them with disrupters
one at conn.
There are none
of our security officers
on the Bridge.
They must have taken us
by surprise.
It appears that we
can move objects
in this time frame.
Maybe we could do something
to help Will.
I'm wary about making changes
in this time continuum
until we understand more
about what's going on.
Captain, the equipment
is no longer functioning.
However, the information
currently displayed
indicates there was a massive
power surge in Engineering.
Security teams
had just been sent
to Transporter Room Three
and to Sick Bay.
Counselor, will you go
to Sick Bay and investigate?
Mr. Data, go to
main Engineering.
See if you
can determine
the cause of that power surge.
I'll be
in Transporter Room Three.
Mr. La Forge.
La Forge here, sir.
Will you lock on to our signals?
I want you to transport
Counselor Troi to...
I'd rather not, Captain.
We've got limited power
and your isolation fields
consume a lot of energy.
Understood.
We'll use the Jefferies tube.
Let's go.
TROI:
Maybe we can
go around them.
No.
We'll find an alternative route.
Let's go back up.
( gasping )
( sighing )
Excuse me, Mr. Worf.
Captain...
Counselor,
take a look at this.
It appears that Mr. Worf had
just beamed these three on board
and according to this
three other Romulans
had been beamed
directly to Sick Bay
just seconds earlier.
I know, I just
saw them.
What are we doing
transporting Romulans
on board the ship
in the middle of a battle?
They don't have
any weapons
and that one
looks injured.
If they were part
of an invasion
then why are they unarmed?
It doesn't make any sense.
Captain, there's something
I have to tell you.
Dr. Crusher has been hit
by a disrupter blast
at point-blank range.
If time returns to normal
I don't see how
she can survive.
Data to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Mr. Data.
Please come
to Engineering immediately.
It is urgent.
What's the problem,
Mr. Data?
Captain, I believe
I have found the cause
of the power surge.
There is a warp core
breach in progress.
It is the flash point
of a warp core explosion
and it is expanding.
Expanding?
I thought that time
was suspended on this ship.
We were incorrect, sir.
I have determined that
time is moving forward
at an infinitesimal rate.
Why didn't we
notice it before?
Our initial
conclusion was based
on our observations
of the crew.
The warp core breach moves
at a much faster rate.
The motion of the cloud
is within my visual
detection threshold.
At its current rate
of expansion
it will consume
the Enterprise
in approximately
nine hours, 17 minutes.
Is there anything
we can do to stop it?
It is no longer a question
of stopping it, sir.
The explosion
has already occurred.
The fact that it is moving
slowly changes nothing.
Astonishing to see it
frozen like this.
Do we know
what caused the breach?
No. However, the console
displays indicate
a power transfer
in progress
between the Enterprise
and the Romulan ship
at the moment
time decelerated.
That is why
there is a second beam
between the two ships.
Why would we be
sending them power?
Perhaps we should go
aboard the Romulan ship.
The answer
to that question may...
( Picard laughing )
Captain?
( gasping )
Captain,
are you all right?
My head.
Oh...
Dizzy.
I can't...
No!
No! No!
Troi to la Forge!
Get us out of here, now!
No! No!
It looks like you weren't
completely protected
from the effects
of the other time continuum.
The neuro-physical stress
must have been overwhelming.
DATA:
In much the same way
deep-sea divers
experience
nitrogen narcosis
you experienced a form
of temporal narcosis.
PICARD:
Can we modify
the subspace isolators
to give us
better protection?
LA FORGE:
I don't think so.
I'd say the best thing
we can do right now
is to be careful--
limit our exposure
to their time frame.
I'd say no longer
than ten minutes per trip
and we should probably
stick together
while we're there,
just in case.
Very well.
Well, the first step is to find
out why the Enterprise
was transferring power
to the Romulan ship.
I think we should
begin our search
in the Romulan Engine Room.
Counselor
you spent several days
on a Romulan vessel.
You probably know more about
the layouts than anyone here.
Perhaps...
( moaning )
Captain, it might be better
if you stayed here this time
and gave yourself
a chance to recover.
Yes, very well.
I will monitor
your progress from here
but just remember--
ten minutes, no more.
TROI:
Yes, Captain.
Geordi, there should be a power
utilization monitor over there.
Data.
This is
highly unusual.
The crew is not
at battle stations.
The ship is on
evacuation alert.
Is that why the Romulans
were being transported
to the Enterprise?
Take a look at this.
There's an energy feedback
returning through
the transfer beam.
It's probably what overloaded
the Enterprise's engines
and caused the core breach.
DATA:
Perhaps the warbird was trying
to destroy the Enterprise.
I don't think so.
According to this
the Romulans were
actually trying
to shut down
the power transfer.
Whatever happened,
this is beginning
to look less and less
like a Romulan attack.
Data, why don't
we take a look
at their engine readouts?
Geordi, the engine core
is completely inactive.
That's impossible.
The Romulans use an artificial
quantum singularity
as their power source.
Once it's activated,
it can't be shut down.
Well, let's take
a closer look.
I think we found
the problem.
It appears to be
a highly focused aperture
in the space-time continuum.
Its energy signature
matches that
of the temporal fragments
we observed earlier.
However, it is approximately
1.2 million times as intense.
I believe this may be the origin
of the temporal fragmentation.
What are those
dark spots?
I am not certain.
They exhibit a complex
bioelectric pattern
very possibly organic.
Organic?
From the molecular
configuration, it appears...
( tricorder beeping )
The aperture is beginning
to fluctuate.
I believe...
ROMULAN 1:
There is an energy buildup
in the phase
compensation levels.
ROMULAN 2:
Check the main
distribution matrix.
That's not it--
the matrix is clear.
It's the power transfer
from the Enterprise.
I'm reading
a massive feedback.
Systems are beginning
to overload.
Notify the Enterprise
to shut down the power
transfer immediately.
They're unable to comply.
Their power interlocks
won't disengage.
We'll have to interrupt
it ourselves.
Disconnect
the transfer beam.
ROMULAN 3:
There is no pressure.
ROMULAN 2:
There is an impending
warp core breach.
Shut down all systems!
( voices speaking backwards )
DATA:
I believe my
tricorder emissions
caused the temporal aperture
to activate.
I suggest we avoid
exposing it
to any further
energy emissions.
When time resumed
did you observe any activity
in the Engine Room
that might suggest
what the Romulans were doing?
They may have been attempting
to eject their engine core.
I thought I heard
one of the engineers
say something about
a power transfer--
something about
an energy feedback.
Yes, Captain.
It looks to me like they
were trying to stop
whatever was happening here.
Mr. La Forge
from where you are,
can you determine
what is happening
on the Romulan Bridge?
I think so, Captain.
Wait.
Something's not right here.
Data, was this man always
standing right here?
( gasping )
( moaning )
He's in neural shock.
We must get him
to the runabout.
There isn't time.
He's dying.
At least this way
he'll be alive in
the other time frame.
We might have a chance
to save him later.
Is the Romulan still alive?
Yes, but...
I am getting
unusual readings
from his bio-scan.
I am not certain
he is a Romulan.
His cellular structure
does not conform
to any known species.
His bioelectric patterns
are in a state
of temporal flux.
I do not believe
this being
is native to our
time continuum.
Mr. Data, you said that
you found organic matter
in the temporal aperture.
Correct, sir.
I'd like to take a closer
look at those readings.
This is a biospectral analysis
of the temporal aperture.
The organic readings
originated
from these dark spots.
They appear to contain
some sort of energy patterns.
Can you isolate one of them
and magnify?
They look like...
cellular clusters.
DATA:
Its bioelectric patterns
are similar to those
of the alien's.
However, they are
significantly less complex.
Its cellular structure
appears to be in
a state of mitosis.
Data, this could be
some sort of embryo.
It is possible.
If I could further scan
the aperture
it might be possible to...
( alien groaning )
TROI:
Captain.
( deep, resonating voice ):
Must... save...
No...
Who are you?
This body is not mine.
It was necessary to assume it
to exist in your time.
Why are you here?
We had to come... to save them.
They were in danger.
Who were
in danger?
Our young.
They will die
in the gravity well.
It is artificial.
Artificial gravity well?
Do you mean
the Romulan engine core?
Yes.
Our young are trapped.
We must get them out.
Return them
to our time.
His molecular structure
is destabilizing.
How were your young
trapped in the core?
We must use
a natural gravity well
to incubate our young.
We thought the Romulan core
would suffice.
It did not.
DATA:
Captain, I believe the aliens
mistook
the artificial singularity
which the Romulans use
in their engine
for a natural one,
a black hole.
They tried to use it as a nest.
That's what deactivated
the warbird's engine core
so the Romulans sent out
a distress call.
PICARD:
The Enterprise responded
and found the warbird suffering
from an apparent engine failure
and they attempted
a power transfer.
ALIEN:
Power transfer.
We must stop power transfer.
Ruptured time...
destroy our young...
When the power transfer
came into contact
with the alien nest
I believe it disrupted
the space-time
continuum.
Did you attack the Enterprise?
Yes.
Had to stop power transfer.
Are there any others
like you here?
One... one other.
Do you know where he is?
Could he help us
restore normal time?
I estimate the core breach
will consume the Enterprise
in approximately seven hours,
two minutes.
Is it possible to lock
onto the core itself--
beam it into space?
No, sir.
We would have
to surround the core
with a subspace isolation field.
It is not possible to generate
a field of that magnitude
from the runabout.
Mr. Data...
When you scanned the temporal
aperture with your tricorder
it caused time to move forwards
and then back again.
Correct, sir.
What if we could
reverse that process?
Cause time to move backwards
and then forwards.
We might be able to run
time back to a point
before the warp core
breach occurred
and then find a way
to prevent
the power transfer.
And then, when time
goes forward again...
the breach never happens.
DATA:
I could attempt
to remodulate
the tricorder's
delta-band emissions.
It should be possible
to better control
the temporal
aperture.
Make it so.
If this works, we may
not have much time
to prevent the
power transfer.
We'll have to decide
precisely where to
be and what to do
the very instant that time
begins to move backwards.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
After placing
the modified tricorder
on the Romulan ship
we have returned
to the Enterprise.
DATA:
I have reached
Engineering, Captain.
Standing by.
Acknowledged.
Counselor, are you in position?
Ready, Captain.
All right, Mr. Data.
Initiating tricorder emissions.
( beeping )
( voices speaking backwards )
( alarm wailing )
Captain...
PICARD:
Go ahead, Mr. Data.
The warp core breach
has been reversed, sir.
Be ready to stop
the power transfer, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
You must stop!
COMPUTER:
Specified energy systems
have been initialized.
The power transfer
can now be engaged.
Do not initiate
that power transfer.
I'm sorry, sir.
I already have.
We must shut it down.
The transfer beam
is at saturation, sir.
It can't be disengaged.
Computer, place a level-three
containment field
around the warp core.
Containment field activated.
( yelling )
RIKER:
Damage report.
MAN:
Shields down to 27%.
Oh!
MAN:
Primary phaser array...
Captain?
No time to explain,
Number One.
Continue the evacuation
of the Romulan ship.
You'll find La Forge
in the Romulan Engine Room.
Beam him directly to Sick Bay.
Step back, now.
CRUSHER:
It's all right, Deanna.
He wasn't firing at me.
ROMULAN:
There was an alien here
who'd taken Romulan form.
I was firing at her.
The doctor
got in the way.
Where did she go?
PICARD:
Status, Mr. Data.
I was attacked
by another alien, sir.
I was unable to prevent
the power transfer.
It cannot be disengaged, sir.
A core breach is again imminent.
Can we move
the ship?
The feedback
from the transfer beam
would tear us apart.
Patch me into the
navigational control
of the runabout.
Got it.
I'm bringing the runabout in.
PICARD:
Mr. Data?
The core breach
has been prevented, sir.
Data, it appears that
severing the power transfer
has not only prevented
the core breach
but it has also
restored space-time to normal.
The alien who attacked me
has vanished, sir.
PICARD:
The warbird
has vanished as well.
Judging from the residual
temporal fluctuations
I believe they have returned
to their own time continuum.
Captain?
( sighs )
It's going to take
a little time to
explain, Number One.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46945.3.
We successfully evacuated
the crew of the Romulan ship
and we're on course
to the Neutral Zone
to bring them home.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Where's that cat of yours?
Spot is sleeping, sir.
Why do you ask?
No reason.
I've worked out the
new rotation schedules.
I'd like you to cross-check
the personnel assignments.
Notify the department heads.
Your Bridge shift
begins at 2300 hours.
Understood, sir.
What are you doing?
Recent events
have compelled me to study
how humans perceive
the passage of time.
For example, I have often
heard people comment
that time seems to pass
more slowly in one instance
or more quickly in another.
In reality,
the actual passage of time
remains fixed.
Hmm.
I suppose it depends on
how people perceive time.
Every situation's different.
It depends on how you feel.
I have been testing the aphorism
"a watched pot never boils."
I have boiled
the same amount of water
in this kettle 62 times.
In some cases,
I have ignored the kettle.
In others,
I have watched it intently.
In every instance
the water reaches
its boiling point
in precisely 51.7 seconds.
It appears I am not capable
of perceiving time
any differently
than my internal chronometer.
Well, why don't you turn it off?
Sir?
Data, people do not have
internal chronometers.
Why don't you see what happens
if you turn yours off?
Thank you, sir.
I will try that.
Just don't be late
for your shift.
( kettle whistling )