But then I said,
"In that frame of reference,
"the perihelion of Mercury
would have precessed in
the opposite direction."
( laughing )
That is a
great story.
Quite amusing, Dr. Hawking.
You see, Sir Isaac,
the joke depends
on an understanding
of the relativistic curvature
of space-time.
If two non-inertial reference
frames are in relative--
Do not patronize me, sir.
I invented physics.
The day that apple
fell on my head
was the most momentous day
in the history of science.
Not the apple story again.
That story is generally
considered to be apocryphal.
What?! How dare you?!
Perhaps we should
return to the game, hmm?
Now, let's see,
where were we?
Yes, you raised Mr. Data four,
which means that,
um, the bet is...
seven to me?
The bet is ten.
Can't you do simple arithmetic?
( sighs )
I don't even know
why I'm here in the
first place.
What is the point of
playing this ridiculous game?
When I play poker
with my shipmates,
it often appears to
be a useful forum
for exploring the different
facets of humanity.
I was curious to see how
three of history's
greatest minds
would interact
in this setting.
So far, it has proved
to be most illuminating.
And profitable.
( chuckles )
Can we get this
over with, please?
It's your bet.
I raise 50.
Blast! I fold.
I fold as well.
The uncertainty principle will
not help you now, Stephen, hmm?
All the quantum fluctuations
in the universe
will not change
the cards
in your hand.
I call.
You are bluffing,
and you will lose.
Wrong again, Albert.
Well... hmm.
RIKER: Red alert. All personnel
report to duty stations.
We will have to
continue this another time.
End program.
RIKER: We've received
a distress call
from the Ohniaka III
outpost.
They said they
were under attack.
Ohniaka III?
There's no strategic
value to that outpost.
Were they able to
identify the attackers?
No, we haven't been
able to raise them
since the initial contact.
We are entering the
Ohniaka system, sir.
Bring us out of warp, Ensign.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Sensors detect one ship
orbiting the third planet.
Its configuration does not match
anything in our records.
Stand by phasers
and photon torpedoes.
Hail them, Mr. Worf.
No response, sir.
Put them on screen.
It does not appear to be
attacking the outpost, sir.
They might have attacked
before we got here.
Or they might simply
be another victim.
What about the outpost?
There is a great deal of
electromagnetic interference.
I am unable to determine
whether there are
any life-forms present.
Worf, Data,
you're with me.
These wounds were caused
by a forced-plasma beam
similar to a Ferengi
hand phaser.
This looks brutal,
even for the Ferengi.
Any sign of the survivors?
Electromagnetic interference
is still making it difficult
to get a
precise reading.
How many people were assigned
to this outpost?
274.
All right, we're gonna need
to do a room-to-room search.
Worf, you and Corelki start
searching the north wing.
You and I'll take the south.
Aye, sir.
Mechanism appears
to be jammed, sir.
RIKER:
There's not much damage.
Doesn't look like
they were interested
in the station--
just the people.
I have bypassed
the primary system.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Evasive maneuvers, Ensign.
Return fire.
Shields down to 80%.
Compensating with
auxiliary power.
You have killed Torsus.
I will make you
suffer for this.
Biological organism-- Klingon.
Biological organism-- human.
( grunts )
Stop it.
Stop.
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
Artificial life-form.
Starfleet rank--
Lieutenant Commander.
Name-- Data.
LA FORGE: Captain, the alien
ship is breaking orbit.
Plot an intercept
course, Ensign.
Fire torpedoes.
They're gone, sir.
Our sensors indicate
there was some kind
of subspace distortion
just before they disappeared.
I'll have to study
these readings
before I can get any
more specific than that.
Take us back to Ohniaka III.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Data?
Data, are you
all right?
Yes, sir.
What happened?
I got angry.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46982.1.
Because of his unusual behavior
on the planet's surface,
Commander Data has asked to be
temporarily relieved of duty.
Unfortunately, this means
he will not be able
to help us investigate
a disturbing new change
in the behavior of the Borg.
They were fast, aggressive,
almost vicious.
It was more like fighting
Klingons... than Borg.
No offense.
None taken.
There was another
difference.
I don't believe they were
part of the Borg collective.
I think they were
acting as individuals.
What?
One of them referred
to himself as "I."
And that Borg showed
concern for a fallen comrade.
He even called
him by name.
The only Borg who had
a name was Hugh,
and we gave it to him.
Maybe Hugh has something to do
with this change
in their behavior.
Did they show any interest
in assimilating you
or your technology?
They seemed more concerned
with the death
of their colleague
and with destroying us.
I didn't see anything
that suggested
they wanted
to assimilate anybody.
The Borg's entire existence
was centered around
acquiring cultures
and technology.
If that's changed,
then they must
have a new objective.
We have to find out
what it is.
Mr. Worf, from this moment on,
I want to maintain
a level-2 security alert.
Post armed officers
on every deck.
Aye, sir.
Number One,
I want you to analyze
our sensor readings
of the Borg ship.
Try to determine if it was
something they constructed
or an alien ship
that they captured.
Then run an analysis of
this subspace distortion
they used to escape.
Aye, sir.
I'm gonna contact
Starfleet Command.
Hmm.
Well, your positronic
net checks out.
Everything else looks fine.
My internal diagnostic
also finds nothing wrong.
I don't know, Data.
There's nothing here
that would indicate anything
that might cause
any sort of
behavioral anomaly.
I agree.
Geordi...
I believe I have experienced
my first emotion.
No offense, Data,
but how would you know
a flash of anger from
some odd kind of power surge?
You are correct in that I have
no frame of reference
to confirm my hypothesis.
In fact,
I am unable to provide
a verbal description
of the experience.
Perhaps you could describe
how it feels to be angry.
I could then use
that as a reference.
Yeah, okay.
Well, when I
feel angry,
first, I, uh...
first, I feel... hostile.
Could you describe
feeling hostile?
Well, yeah, it's
like feeling...
belligerent, combative.
Could you describe
feeling angry
without referring
to other feelings?
No, I guess I can't.
I just...
feel angry.
That was my
experience as well.
I simply felt angry.
Well, let's say you're right
and this is a real emotion.
How is that
possible?
I do not know.
Perhaps I have
evolved to the point
where emotions are
within my grasp.
Perhaps I will experience
other emotions as time goes by.
Well, I hope you're right.
I'd hate to think
that anger
is all you're
capable of feeling.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 46984.6.
No additional Borg attacks
have been reported
in the past two days.
However, Starfleet has
dispatched Admiral Nechayev
to take command in this sector
in preparation
for a possible Borg invasion.
There will be 15 starships
in this sector
by the day
after tomorrow.
The Gorkon will be
my flagship.
You'll take command
of task force three
consisting of
the Enterprise,
the Crazy Horse,
and the Agamemnon.
Understood.
Captain, I've read the report
that you submitted
to Admiral Brooks last year
regarding the Borg
you called "Hugh",
and I've been trying to figure
out why you let him go.
I thought that I had
made that clear.
As I understand it,
you found a single Borg
at a crash site,
brought it aboard
the Enterprise,
studied it, analyzed it,
and eventually found a way
to send it back to the Borg
with a program
that would have destroyed
the entire collective
once and for all.
But instead, you nursed
the Borg back to health,
treated it like a guest,
gave it a name
and then sent it home.
Why?
When Hugh was separated
from the Borg collective,
he began to grow, to evolve
into something
other than an automaton.
He became a person.
When that happened,
I felt I had no choice
but to respect his rights
as an individual.
Of course you had a choice.
You could have taken
the opportunity to rid
the Federation of
a mortal enemy--
one that has killed
tens of thousands
of innocent people,
and which may kill even more.
No one is more aware
of the danger than I am.
But I'm also bound by my oath
and my conscience
to uphold certain principles.
And I will not sacrifice
them in order to--
Your priority
is to safeguard
the lives of
Federation citizens,
not to wrestle with
your conscience.
Now, I want
to make it clear
that if you have a similar
opportunity in the future--
an opportunity to
destroy the Borg--
you are under orders
to take advantage of it.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
For the past six hours
I have attempted to produce
an emotional response
by subjecting myself
to various stimuli.
Like what?
I listened to several operas
known to be uplifting.
I watched three
holodeck programs
designed to be humorous,
and I made four attempts
to induce sexual desire
by subjecting myself
to erotic imagery.
What happened?
Nothing.
I'm curious.
Why are you ignoring
the one emotion
you've already experienced?
Why aren't you trying to
make yourself angry again?
Anger is a negative emotion.
I wanted to concentrate
on something more positive.
Data, feelings aren't
positive and negative.
They simply exist.
It's what we do
with those feelings
that becomes
good or bad.
( sighs )
For example,
feeling angry about an
injustice could lead someone
to take a positive action
to correct it.
But my study of
humanity indicates
that there are some emotions
that are harmful,
such as jealousy
or hatred.
Those are very strong emotions,
and you're right--
very little good
can come from them.
But I don't think that
an exploration of anger
need necessarily
lead to hatred or malice.
But what if it does,
Counselor?
What if those are
the only emotions
I am capable of experiencing?
Would that not make me
a bad person?
We've served together
for a long time,
and I think I've come
to know you pretty well.
I have to believe
if you ever reach
your goal of
becoming human...
you won't become a bad one.
I wish I were as confident
as you, Counselor.
When I was fighting
the Borg, I felt angry.
But when I think back
on the incident,
I realize that
I was also experiencing
another sensation.
It was not the
same as anger,
but I think it
was an emotion.
When exactly did you
feel this other emotion?
It was just after I
had killed the Borg.
I looked down
at his body.
I felt something.
If you had to give
this feeling a name,
what would you call it?
I believe... it was...
pleasure.
Red alert.
All hands to battle stations.
Lay in a course.
Engage, warp nine.
We've received a distress call
from the New Berlin colony.
They're under attack.
What's our ETA?
At warp nine,
15 minutes, 30 seconds.
Contact the Crazy Horse
and the Agamemnon.
Have them standing by
in case we need them--
Captain, incoming message
from the New Berlin colony.
They have...
canceled their
distress call.
Evidently, a Ferengi
trading ship
entered their system
and someone panicked.
Third time today.
Stand down red alert.
Reduce speed, return to
our patrol route.
Mr. Worf, acknowledge
the signal from New Berlin
and transmit another copy
of Starfleet's
ship recognition protocols,
and tell them to
read it this time.
Aye, sir.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have been on patrol
for 16 hours
and there are no reports
of further Borg activity.
But tensions continue
to run high
on the colonies and outposts
in this sector.
Do I have a name?
I'm Beverly,
he's Geordi,
and you... you...
LA FORGE:
No, no, wait a minute.
That's it... Hugh.
We are Hugh.
( door chimes )
PICARD:
Come.
I thought you might
like to see this.
Geordi's analysis of
the subspace distortion
the Borg used to escape.
An artificially created
energy conduit?
That could be anything.
We don't have enough
information at this point--
I don't want excuses,
Number One, I want answers!
I'm sorry.
He was here in
this room, Will.
I could have rid the Federation
of a mortal threat,
and I let him go.
Sending Hugh back to the Borg
was a very risky...
a very dangerous choice.
But it was the
moral thing to do.
Well, it may turn out
that the moral thing to do
was not the right
thing to do.
Stop it.
Stop. Stop.
Stop.
Data, am I interrupting
something?
Yes.
But it is all right.
Do you need me?
Uh, I... wanted to see if you
were ready to return to duty.
I need some help
with an analysis
on the ship the Borg
were using.
I believe I am able
to resume my duties.
Data, exactly what is it
that you're doing here?
I am attempting to
recreate the experience
which caused my initial
outburst of anger.
Any luck?
None so far.
I have almost completed
this experiment.
May I finish before we
return to Engineering?
Yeah, sure.
Computer,
reset Borg simulation
to time index 2.1.
Increase Borg strength by 20%.
Run program.
Stop it.
Stop.
Stop. Stop.
Computer,
reset simulation
to time index 2.1.
Increase Borg strength
by 30%.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
A 30% increase would
exceed safety limits.
Geordi, the computer requires
a voice authorization
of two senior officers
in order to disable
the safety routine.
Will you help me?
Data, wait a minute.
That thing could
kill you.
During the original incident,
the Borg presented a genuine
danger to my life.
Since the holodeck
safety routine is in place,
I know my life
is not in danger.
Since I am trying to
duplicate the conditions
of the original incident
as closely as possible,
I must also attempt to duplicate
my jeopardy as well.
Data, we're talking
about an experiment here.
You can't put your life
on the line
just to prove some theory.
This experiment
may hold the key
to something I have sought
all my life.
( sighs )
This is crazy.
There's gotta be
another way.
Can't you think
of some other way
to make yourself angry?
I have tried
other stimuli,
but they have been
unsuccessful.
I understand your objections,
but it is my life,
and I have a right to
risk it, if I choose.
Yeah, and I'm your friend
and I'm not gonna just
stand around
and let you do this.
RIKER: Red alert. All hands,
battle stations.
Confirmed.
The MS 1 colony
is under attack.
Doesn't it seem
strange to you
that there have been
two Borg attacks,
and the Enterprise
has been the nearest ship
in both instances?
Captain, we are
nearing the MS system.
I have located
the Borg ship.
It is heading away
from the colony.
Take us out of warp
near that ship.
Stand by to lock
phasers on target.
WORF:
Within visual range.
On screen.
PICARD:
Lay in an intercept course.
Full impulse.
Lock phasers.
We are closing, sir.
Within phaser range
in 30 seconds.
Sensors are detecting
a subspace distortion
forming directly ahead
of the Borg ship.
Well, they're not gonna
get away with it this time.
Picard to Engineering.
Transfer auxiliary
and emergency power
to the impulse engines.
LA FORGE:
Acknowledged.
Impulse engines
are now at 125%.
Within phaser range
in ten seconds.
We appear to be caught in
some kind of energy matrix.
All engines back full.
Shields failing.
We are being
pulled inside.
WORF: Inertial
dampers failing.
Main power
is off-line.
I am switching
to backups.
Picard to Engineering.
Can we transfer
auxiliary power
to the warp nacelles?
Try to break us out
by using the...
We have returned
to normal space.
Navigational systems
are still off-line.
I will attempt to
make a celestial fix
using secondary systems.
Captain, the Borg ship
is directly ahead.
It is coming about.
On screen.
Shields down to 16%.
MAN:
Get down!
RIKER:
Franklin's dead, sir.
Is everyone else
all right?
Aye, sir.
Security reports there are
no other intruders aboard.
Captain...
the Borg ship is gone.
Sensor logs
indicate they entered
the distortion field
30 seconds ago.
They beamed on board
as a diversion
to give their ship
time to escape.
This is another change
in the Borg behavior.
They left their dead
instead of vaporizing them.
DATA:
Captain.
This one is still alive.
I've stabilized
his condition.
He's still pretty weak, but he
should make a full recovery.
Can you awaken him?
Yes, but it's very risky.
His heart rate and
blood pressure are up--
Do it.
All right.
Lower the force-field.
What is your designation?
I do not have
a designation.
My name is Crosis.
Crosis?
How did you get that name?
It was given to me by the one.
Who is that?
The one who will
destroy you.
But you are Borg.
Your goal is not to destroy
but to assimilate us
into your collective.
We do not assimilate inferior
biological organisms.
We destroy them.
PICARD: Tell me more
about this "one."
Does he... have a name?
Is he called Hugh?
Klingon--
shatter cranial exoskeleton
at the tricipital lobe.
Death is immediate.
Why must this "one" destroy
biological organisms?
Human-- sever spinal cord
at third vertebrae.
Death is immediate.
I am Locutus of Borg.
You will respond
to my questions.
This is going nowhere.
Doctor, I want you to do
an autopsy on the other one.
Compare the differences
with what we learned
of Hugh's anatomy.
See if there have been
any recent modifications
which might explain
these behavioral differences.
Data, run a biospectral
analysis on this Borg.
See if he is trying to send a
subspace signal to the others.
Aye, sir.
You are not
like the others.
You do not have to
be destroyed.
You can be assimilated.
I do not wish
to be assimilated.
Resistance... is futile.
You will not resist
what you've wanted
all your life.
I was like you once--
without feeling.
But the one helped me.
He can help you, too.
He can help you find emotion.
Have you ever felt a
real emotion, Data?
Yes.
On Ohniaka III, I was...
forced to kill a Borg.
I got angry.
How did it
feel to get angry?
Did it give you pleasure?
It would be unethical
to take pleasure in
another being's death.
You didn't answer
my question.
Did it feel
good to kill?
Yes.
If it is unethical
to take pleasure
from another being's death,
you must be a very
unethical person.
No.
That is not correct.
My creator, Dr. Soong,
gave me a program
which defines
my sense of right and wrong.
In essence, I have
a conscience.
It didn't seem to be functioning
on Ohniaka III
when you felt pleasure
in killing that Borg.
Step away from
the force-field.
Your proximity is interfering
with my scan.
You enjoyed it--
that surge of emotion
inside you--
as you watched the life
drain from your victim.
It was unlike anything
you've ever felt before.
It was a very...
potent experience.
You'd like to feel
that way again.
Yes.
You'd do anything to
feel that way again...
even if it meant
killing someone.
No.
That would not be ethical.
You don't sound
very sure of yourself.
Is your ethical
program functioning?
Data...
do you have a friend?
Yes.
His name is Geordi.
If it meant that you
could feel emotions again,
the way you did
on Ohniaka III,
would you kill
your friend?
Would you kill Geordi?
Yes... I would.
Our current theory is
that the Borg have established
several transwarp conduits
through subspace.
The ship, when
entering the conduit,
is immediately accelerated
to an extremely high warp
velocity.
It's like falling
into a fast-moving river
and being swept away
by the current.
How fast would a ship travel
through one of these conduits?
Oh, we don't know.
Normal subspace limitations
don't apply to
transwarp variables.
But I'd say, based on
the distance we covered
during our trip
through the conduit,
the speed would have to be
at least 20 times faster
than our maximum warp.
How do they open
the conduits?
The Borg ship emitted some kind
of high-energy tachyon pulse
just before we saw
the subspace distortion.
Seems as though the conduits
are keyed to respond
to tachyon transmissions
of a specific frequency.
Is there any way for
us to duplicate--
Captain, a shuttlecraft
has left Bay Two.
Who authorized
the launch?
There was no
authorization.
Picard to Shuttlecraft.
Identify yourself
and return to
the ship immediately.
Mr. Worf...
lock on with a tractor beam
and return it to the ship.
Aye, sir.
The tractor beam
has been disabled.
The command override
is not functioning.
Captain, I'm picking up
a tachyon surge.
Looks like whoever's
in the shuttle
is trying to trigger
the transwarp conduit.
Do we know who's on board?
It is the Borg prisoner...
and Commander Data.
Mr. La Forge, can we follow
them into the conduit?
We've got a pretty good reading
of the tachyon pulse they sent.
We might be able
to duplicate it.
The question is,
is Data a prisoner,
or did he go willingly?
The command overrides used
to disable the tractor beam
were Commander Data's.
The Borg could have
downloaded the codes
from Data's
positronic net.
Perhaps Data's recent
flash of emotion
has something
to do with this.
It could have affected
him more profoundly
than we realize.
Either way,
we have to find him.
I've set up a temporary
tachyon matrix
in the main deflector.
I think I can
use it to simulate
the pulse sent by the shuttle.
Mr. Worf, red alert.
All hands--
battle stations.
Bring us to the last known
coordinates of the shuttlecraft.
Shields up, weapons ready.
Mr. La Forge?
Energizing the matrix.
Emitting tachyons in
the lower bandwidth.
Sensors show no unusual
subspace activity.
All right, switching to
the secondary bandwidth.
Nothing.
Maybe... if I try
alternating the frequencies.
Captain, there is an
energy fluctuation
directly ahead of us.
It is the subspace distortion.
Take us in, Ensign,
one-half impulse.
Power levels
are down to 67%.
Compensating with
auxiliary power.
Report.
Navigational sensors show
that we've traveled...
65 light years from
our previous position.
( sighs )
Can you locate the shuttle?
No, sir.
There is no indication
of the shuttle within
range of our sensors.
Maybe we can find an energy
signature from their engines.
Captain.
Yes, Mr. La Forge?
I've scanned three
different star systems
within sensor range.
There is evidence of at least
two advanced civilizations,
but I'm reading
no life signs.
But there are indications that
plasma weapons have been fired
in those systems recently.
The Borg have been busy.
I think we've found the
shuttle's energy signature.
They were heading 247, mark 059.
Lay in that course, Ensign,
and engage at full impulse.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
We've traced the
shuttle's energy signature
to this point on the surface,
but there's too much
interference to
scan the location.
Are they intentionally
jamming our sensors?
It looks more like a
natural phenomenon.
There's an unusually
high amount of EM interference
in the planet's magnetosphere.
Can we transport
through the interference?
We could, but there could be
50 Borg down there
waiting for us,
and we'd never even know it.
I think we have
to take the risk.
Agreed.
Take a well-armed away team
and transport down
to those coordinates.
Have the transporter chief keep
a permanent lock
on your signal,
so we can get you
out of there at the first
sign of trouble.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, you're with me.
Riker to Enterprise.
We're on the surface.
There's no sign
of any Borg...
or Data.
The shuttle appears
to be abandoned.
The EM interference is
limiting the tricorder range.
It is useless
beyond 100 meters.
There are no structures
in the area.
They could have gone anywhere.
Can you determine
how long they've been gone
from the shuttlecraft?
The engine's been off
a little over three hours.
Stand by, Number One.
Assuming that they're
still together,
how far could they have
traveled in three hours?
Well, Data can move
pretty fast
even over rough terrain,
but based on what we know
about the Borg, I don't
think they should be able
to move any faster
than you or I.
They might have been able
to get 15 to 20 kilometers
away from the shuttle by now.
Picard to Riker.
Riker here.
I'm gonna start sending
down other away teams.
Set up a command post and
begin mapping a search plan.
RIKER: Understood.
Picard out.
I want to use the shuttlecraft
for low-level reconnaissance.
Have the designated pilots
assemble in main shuttlebay.
Aye, sir.
And all available personnel,
including you and me,
we'll begin to put together
four-man away teams.
I'll leave a skeleton crew
on board the ship.
Who'll be in command
of the Enterprise?
Any last orders?
If the Borg should attack,
don't wait for me
or anyone else
to return to the ship,
but take the Enterprise
to the transwarp conduit.
Return to Federation space.
Got it.
Good luck, Jean-Luc.
Good luck... Captain.
I've sent out 12 teams so far.
I've got your team
searching section Gamma 2-4.
Worf and I will take Theta 1-6
when the last team comes down.
Who's manning
the command post?
Wallace and Towles.
Ready?
( tricorder beeping )
Anything, Mr. La Forge?
Well... no.
Nothing, sir.
What if we modified
the phasers to send out
a luvetric pulse?
It might create a
resonance fluctuation
in Data's power cells.
Home in on that response
with the tricorders.
Yeah, I thought about that.
The only problem is that
the pulse would probably
have to be so powerful
that it would destroy
Data's positronic
net in the process.
Captain?
I think
I found something.
Come on.
I'm having a very
difficult time
scanning the interior.
Can you tell if it
was built by the Borg?
Mmm... I don't think so.
There are no Borg
energy signatures.
But there is a door or...
a hatch or something,
about 20 meters this way.
This seems to be some
kind of meeting place.
PICARD: Well, it certainly
hasn't been abandoned.
Something's wrong.
I can't get any kind
of energy signatures
from these light sources.
It's a dampening field.
This entire structure could
be shielded from our sensors.
Let's go.
BORG:
There they are!
( Borg yelling )
( yelling intensifies )
MAN:
Stop!
Data.
That's not Data.
What?
You should listen to her,
Captain.
She's way ahead of you.
Lore.
Right...
and I'm not alone.
The sons of Soong
have joined together.
And together...
we will destroy
the Federation.
( excited shouting )