ANNOUNCER:
Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
Stop.
Stop!
It was just after I
had killed the Borg.
I felt something.
I believe... it was...
pleasure.
I don't believe
they were part of
the Borg collective.
One of them referred
to himself as "I."
The only Borg who had
a name was Hugh.
We are Hugh.
PICARD:
He was here in this room.
I could have rid the Federation
of a mortal threat
and I let him go.
The Borg have established
several transwarp conduits
through subspace.
DATA:
Get down!
I was like you once--
without feeling
but the one helped me.
He can help you, too.
He can help you
find emotion.
You will not resist
what you've wanted
all your life.
If the Borg should attack
don't wait for me or anyone else
to return to the ship
but take the Enterprise
to the transwarp conduit.
Return to Federation space.
( Borg chattering )
MAN:
Stop!
Lore.
The sons of Soong
have joined together.
And together
we will destroy
the Federation.
ANNOUNCER:
And now, the conclusion.
What do you think of
my followers, Picard?
Impressive, aren't they?
I'm not particularly impressed.
All you've done is teach them
to enjoy killing.
DATA:
You are wrong,
Captain.
My brother and I serve
a much higher purpose.
Data, I can sense
feelings in you.
Yes. My brother
has made that possible.
He gave you the chip--
the one Dr. Soong
made for you.
( scoffs )
No, no, no, no, no.
I still have
the emotional program
my father designed.
I wouldn't want to give it up.
It's what has given me such
a strong sense of family--
an intense desire to reunite
with my dear brother.
How did he do it, Data?
What made you decide
to come here?
I am talking
to you, Picard.
I will tell you
all you need to know.
You're controlling him
and you've corrupted
the Borg.
( sighing )
You simply don't
understand, do you?
You have no idea
of what has happened here--
how I found my true calling
how the Borg found something
to believe in.
I would like
to learn about that
but I want Data to tell us.
I told you,
I will tell you
what you need to know.
How about that, Data?
He won't even
let you talk.
Do not try to drive
a wedge between us, Captain.
I am loyal to my brother.
LORE:
You see, Picard?
He's not your pawn anymore.
I've helped him to break free
just as I've helped them.
Look at them.
Look at what
I've helped them become.
They're no longer simply
mindless automatons.
They're passionate.
Alive.
Are you saying
that you
caused them
to become individuals?
No. You did that--
you and your friends.
All I did was clean up
the mess you made
when that Borg you befriended
returned to his ship.
Hugh interfaced with the others
and transferred
his sense
of individuality to them.
It nearly destroyed them.
Data, do you remember
when Hugh was on board
the Enterprise?
Do you remember what
you were like then?
That doesn't matter.
It matters to me.
I want to know
what has happened to Data.
What's important
is what I've done here--
how I found my calling.
I know now why I was created.
No one can ever take that
away from me.
Without me,
they would have perished.
When I stumbled
on their ship,
they were lost,
disoriented.
They had no idea
how to function as individuals.
They couldn't even navigate
their own vessel.
They had lost
their sense of purpose.
Well, I gave them their purpose
and they gave me mine.
The Borg aspire
to the perfection
my brother and I represent--
fully artificial life-forms.
We are their future.
The reign
of biological life-forms
is coming to an end.
You, Picard...
and those like you...
... are obsolete.
Take them, brother.
( buzz of Borg conversation )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
CRUSHER:
Acting Captain's log,
supplemental.
The skeleton crew left
on board the Enterprise
is unable to help in the search
for Commander Data.
The planet's unusual EM field
is interfering
with the ship's sensors
severely limiting
their effectiveness.
Ensign, we need to modify
the sensor array
to filter out these EM pulses.
Can you do that?
Yes, sir.
I-I think so.
What's your name?
Taitt, sir.
I don't think
I've seen you before.
I was just posted here
six weeks ago.
Well, Taitt,
bet you never thought
you'd be serving
as tactical officer
after only six weeks.
No, sir, I sure didn't.
I think I've
filtered out
some of the sensor noise.
I'll bring the
modifications on line.
Good work.
Riker to Enterprise.
Go ahead, Will.
I can't contact the captain.
It could just be interference,
but I'd like to be sure.
Understood.
Enterprise to Captain Picard.
Crusher to Picard.
I'm not getting
a com signal
from anyone on
the captain's team.
The last time
they checked in
they were investigating
a structure
in section Gamma 2-5.
Sir, I'm picking up
a vessel closing in
on our location.
Is it a Borg ship?
It seems to match
the configuration of the ship
the Enterprise encountered
at Ohniaka III.
Red alert.
How long before
they're in weapons range?
Uh, about 90 seconds.
No, no, make that 70 seconds.
Crusher to
transporter room three.
Salazar here, sir.
Start transporting
the away teams
off of the surface.
Aye, sir.
Use the transporters
in the cargo bay
if you have to.
I want those teams up here
as fast as possible.
Armstrong, you
and the others
prepare to beam up.
Aye, sir.
Beverly, Worf and I
will stay down here
and look for
the captain's team.
I'm not going
to leave you down there.
You pull as many people
off the surface as you can
and get back to
the transwarp conduit.
The captain's orders were
to get the Enterprise
back to Federation space.
Acknowledged.
Riker out.
Prepare to leave orbit.
Sir, the Borg ship
is powering up
its forward weapons array.
They'll be in firing range
in... in 20 seconds.
Salazar, how many people
do we still have down there?
73, sir.
Put the Borg ship on screen.
Should I raise
shields, sir?
Not yet.
I want to keep
bringing people up
until the last possible second.
TAITT:
Ten seconds.
Stand by to raise shields
and break orbit on my mark.
Five seconds.
Mark.
Shields down to 70%.
Establish a frequency shift
firing pattern
and return fire.
Uh... right.
Direct hit.
No damage.
Helm, set a course
for the conduit, maximum warp.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Sir, the Borg
aren't following us.
Salazar,
how many people
did we leave behind?
47, sir.
Another minute
and we would have had them.
Riker to any team leader.
Lieutenant Powell here, sir.
Round up everybody
who was left behind
take cover and try to avoid
any contact with the Borg.
Aye, sir.
Riker out.
Even if Beverly can get
back to Federation space
it will be a few days
until Starfleet
can get
any ships here.
Until then,
we're on our own.
Data, you must realize that
something has happened to you.
The Data I know
would never have agreed
to be a willing party
to Lore's plan.
I now realize
that my life
aboard the Enterprise
was a waste.
My quest to become human
misguided--
an evolutionary step
in the wrong
direction.
Data, all I'm sensing from you
is anger and hatred.
Have you felt
any other emotions?
There are no other emotions.
Data, just because you haven't
experienced certain emotions
doesn't mean they don't exist.
Lore is only feeding you
the negative ones.
Counselor Troi herself told me
that feelings are not
negative or positive.
It is how we act on them
that makes them good or bad.
Fine
but what about the things
that Lore is proposing?
What about the lives
that have already been lost?
You simply do not understand.
In a quest such as ours,
sacrifices have to be made.
It is regrettable
but the greater good
must be served.
Give me your VISOR.
Why?
Give it to me
or I will take
it by force.
( sighing )
I am not your puppet anymore.
Sir, we've reached
the coordinates
of the conduit.
The tachyon matrix
is energized and ready to go
and Lieutenant Barnaby
has returned from the surface.
He'll be relieving me.
Right. Stand by
to trigger the conduit.
Taitt, I want you
to stay on the bridge.
I'll need a science officer
at the aft station.
Yes, sir.
Helm, set a course to return
to the planet.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
I'm not leaving those people
stranded back there.
An emergency buoy can transmit
a copy of our log entries
to Starfleet
just as easily as we can.
Ensign, prepare a buoy
and launch it when ready.
Aye, sir.
CRUSHER:
Lieutenant,
open the conduit.
TAITT:
Launching buoy now, sir.
Lieutenant,
scan for any Borg ships
between here and the planet.
Sensors detect
no vessels.
We have to assume
the ship that attacked us
is still in orbit.
How long will we have
before they can detect us
and intercept?
If their sensors function
as well as ours
it could be as little
as 30 seconds.
Crusher to Salazar.
How long will it take
to get the rest of the crew
off the surface?
One minute should do it.
We don't have one minute.
How much can you
shave off that?
If I could get
a good lock on them quickly
I might be able to do it
in 45 or 50 seconds.
We need to buy ourselves
15 seconds.
Lieutenant,
is there any way
we can use the planet
as a barrier
to keep the Borg from realizing
we're in orbit?
We can enter orbit
while they're on the far side
of the planet.
And if we delay
dropping out of warp
until the last possible instant
we could gain
a few more seconds.
TAITT:
If your calculations
are even slightly off,
we'd hit the atmosphere.
I'll just have to be sure
my calculations are accurate,
Ensign.
Let's do it.
Helm, hard about.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Still no sign
of the structure.
With all this interference
it could be 100 meters away
and we wouldn't know it.
This could take hours.
I'm picking up
a faint energy reading.
Residual
thermal traces.
Somebody stood here.
The decay rate indicates
it could be human.
They took this path.
There you are, brother.
Here is the VISOR.
May I ask why you wanted it.
Thought it might
look good on me.
What do you think?
Maybe we should work on
your sense of humor, brother.
Actually, I was thinking
La Forge's implants
might make him an
ideal test subject
for my experiment.
All of the Borg you have
experimented on so far
have suffered
extensive brain damage.
Using the humans
to perfect the procedure
will allow us to prevent
any further Borg deaths.
I understand.
Good.
What is it?
This Borg
has disconnected himself
from the others.
He would not let me
hear his thoughts.
( sighs )
I've asked you
to stay linked
to Crosis at all times.
You know that,
don't you?
Yes.
I know this must be
difficult for you.
I know how uncertain
you must feel.
All of these
sensations are new
and they can be
frightening.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
I have doubts.
Of course, you do.
It's only natural.
No one is going
to blame you for that.
But in order
to lose those doubts
to keep fear
and confusion away
I need you to remain
linked to the others
so that their strength
and their confidence
can help you.
I need you, Goval.
I need you to help me
build a future
for the Borg.
I can't do it
without you.
Will you help me?
Yes, I will.
Lore must have told Data
to take my VISOR
because he realized
I could see
a carrier wave that was
radiating from him.
A carrier wave?
Is that how he's
manipulating Data?
I think what's happening
is that Lore is tapping
into the chip
he stole from Dr. Soong
and somehow he's
found a way to transmit
part of that emotional
program to Data.
But the only emotions
Data seems to feel
are negative.
Yeah, I'm sure
that's intentional.
But in order for Data
to be affected by those emotions
Lore would have had
to disable
his ethical program first.
Can we reactivate it?
If I can generate
a phased Kedion pulse
at the right frequency,
that would trigger
Data's subsystems,
and reboot the program.
And although Lore
would still be feeding him
negative emotions at least
Data might listen to us.
Right.
I think it's
worth a try.
So, got any ideas
on how we generate
a Kedion pulse?
( force-field deactivates )
Data, where are
you taking him?
That is not
your concern.
Data, wait.
Let us talk to you.
( distant voices )
( mechanical whirring )
Commander.
( footsteps approaching )
Hugh?
Why are you here
Commander Riker?
Hasn't the crew
of the Enterprise
caused enough damage already?
So, you blame us
for what has happened
to the Borg?
You gave me a sense
of individuality
changed me, then sent me
back to the collective.
You must have known
that change would be
passed on to others.
We considered it.
We knew it was a possibility.
Then you made it possible
for Lore to dominate us.
I cannot accept that.
Lore is only one.
The Borg could
have stopped him.
You don't know
the condition we were in
when he found us.
Before my experience
on the Enterprise
the Borg were
a single-minded collective.
The voices in our heads
were smooth and flowing
but after I returned
those voices began to change.
They became uneven, discordant.
For the first time
individual Borg
had differing ideas
about how to proceed.
We couldn't function.
Some Borg fought each other.
Others simply
shut themselves down.
Many starved to death.
And then, Lore came along.
You probably
can't imagine
what it is like to be
so lost and frightened
that you will listen
to any voice
which promises change.
Even if that voice
insists on controlling you?
That's what
we wanted--
someone to show us
a way out of confusion.
Lore promised clarity
and purpose.
At the beginning,
he seemed like a savior.
The promise of becoming
a superior race--
of becoming
fully artificial--
was compelling.
We gladly did everything
he asked of us
but, after a while,
it became clear
that Lore had no idea
how to keep his promise.
That's when he began talking
about the need for us
to make sacrifices.
Before we realized it,
this was the result.
RIKER:
What happened to them?
Lore began to experiment
trying to remake us
in his image.
This is the result
of my encounter
with the Enterprise,
Commander.
So you can see
I don't particularly
welcome your presence here.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
We just came
to get our people.
We won't cause you
any more trouble.
Tell me about my friend.
Friend?
The human called Geordi.
I wish I could tell you
about him.
We think he may be held
inside the compound.
I cannot help you.
I cannot risk
our being discovered.
Could you at least show us
a way into the compound?
These caverns lead to tunnels
which run beneath the compound.
Some of them connect
with the environmental
control ducts.
Show us.
If we could determine
the geography of the compound
we could form a rescue plan.
( beeping )
Data?
Who's there?
( Picard's voice ):
Geordi.
Captain...
( Picard's voice ):
Shh. We're getting
out of here.
Come on, hurry.
Data was just here.
I think he went
to get something.
( normal voice ):
Too late.
My brother suggested
I try to develop
my sense of humor.
What do you think?
I think it needs
a little work.
( whirring )
What's happening?
I'm attempting
to neutralize
your pain receptors.
What are you going
to do to me?
I'm implanting
nano-cortical fibers
in your cerebrum.
They are designed
to learn
and mimic your
neural firing patterns.
Once they are in place
I will destroy
the existing brain cells.
Then we will see if the
artificial neural network
is able to take over
your cognitive functions.
Data, listen.
Lore is controlling you.
He's transmitting a carrier
wave, which is affecting
your positronic matrix.
If the procedure is successful
your cognitive
processing functions
will be
considerably improved.
Don't you care
that he's manipulating you?
However, there is a 60% chance
you will not survive
the procedure.
I don't care much
for those odds.
Hmm...
They are cause for concern.
However, I still have
Counselor Troi
and Captain Picard.
Odds are at least one
of the procedures
will be successful.
TROI:
Help me!
He tried to escape.
The force-field sent
him into neural shock.
If he dies,
Lore will blame you.
( groaning )
See if the corridor
is empty.
( gasping )
Drop it,
or I'll break his neck.
Take him.
What have you done to him?
I will be back
for him later.
Geordi, are
you in pain?
No, I'm just a little dizzy.
I was able to take
part of a transceiver
from the guard's
interlink system.
I think that it uses
some kind of phased
pulse technology.
Do you think
it could be modified
to generate a Kedion pulse
that would reboot
Data's program?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's possible.
See if you can locate
the phase modulation circuitry.
I'll watch the door.
( clicking )
( beeping )
All right.
I think that I've found it.
Okay, good.
Now, do you see anything
that we might be able to use
as a flux inhibitor?
Hmm...
Sensors still can't
locate the Borg ship.
I'm trying to filter out
the interference.
We'll be within
transporter range
in 19 seconds.
I'm starting to get
sensor resolution.
CRUSHER:
There's the ship.
We'll enter orbit here.
Helm, new course--
heading 052 mark 7.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Stand by to drop
out of warp
in eight seconds.
TAITT:
Once we're in orbit
we should have
about 45 seconds
before they intercept us.
Let's hope it's enough time.
BARNABY:
Emergency deceleration
in five seconds.
Hold on.
Report.
We're in standard orbit, sir.
The Borg ship is
on the planet's far side
and is moving
to intercept.
Bridge to transporter rooms,
begin evacuations.
The Borg will be
in weapons range
in 32 seconds.
We still can't locate
Captain Picard's team
and there's no sign
of Commander Riker
or Lieutenant Worf.
Crusher to Salazar.
Report.
We're pulling
the last teams off right now
but there are six people
still unaccounted for.
CRUSHER:
Keep trying.
BARNABY:
Borg ship is powering up
its weapons array.
Come on, Chief,
it's now or never.
TAITT:
They're preparing to fire.
Raise shields.
( explosion )
BARNABY:
The port nacelle
has been hit.
Helm, get us out of here.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
We've lost warp engines.
Evasive maneuvers, full impulse.
TAITT:
Shields down to 80%.
Fire phasers.
Direct hit.
No damage to the Borg ship.
Shields down to 73%.
What's the status
of the warp engines?
Still down.
We can't outrun them.
Helm, set a new course--
heading 344 mark 6.
Full impulse.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Sir, that heading takes us
directly into the sun.
The data banks should
contain information
on a process called
metaphasic shielding.
I know about
that research.
Commander La Forge was
developing a program
that would implement
metaphasic properties.
Right, how far
along was he?
Well, it's in the data banks
but it's never been tested.
If we had
metaphasic shielding,
we could enter
the sun's corona
but the Borg ship
wouldn't be able to follow.
Can you bring
the program on line?
I can, but we have
no way of knowing
if the shields
will hold.
Sir, hull temperature
is rising-- now at
12,000 degrees C.
Radiation level
nearing 10,000 rads.
Report.
Shields at 62%.
Lieutenant, activate
the metaphasic program.
It's our best shot.
Aye, sir.
Hull temperature
is critical.
We can't withstand
this heat much longer.
Program is on line.
Engaging metaphasic shield now.
Hull temperature dropping.
Down to 7,000 degrees.
Maintain course.
Borg ship has
broken off pursuit.
All stop.
Sir, the Borg ship is taking
up position relative to ours.
They're going to wait
for us to come out.
The question is,
how long can we survive in here?
Well...
I've done everything
that Geordi told me.
Now to activate it.
How are we going
to know whether the pulse
reboots Data's
ethical program?
We'll only tell that
when we see his behavior.
Won't he realize
something's happened to him?
No, that's one program
among thousands.
I just hope that
this force-field
has enough energy...
to trigger the pulse.
You know, Data
I've been thinking about
some of the times we've had.
Like that time we went
sailing on Devala lake.
You remember that?
I have a complete
memory record of that day.
( chuckling )
You decided to go swimming
and when you jumped
out of the boat you sank
straight to the bottom.
I did not have enough buoyancy
to get back to the surface.
You had to walk over a kilometer
along the bottom
to get back to shore.
One kilometer, 46 meters.
It took almost two weeks to get
the water out of your servos.
I am ready to irradiate
your existing brain cells.
Data...
if you ever go back
to the way you were
you might not be able
to forgive yourself
for what you're
about to do.
I am getting
some anomalous readings
from your neural net.
I will need to do further
testing before... I proceed.
Someone will come and take you
back to your cell.
There you are, brother.
Have you made any
progress with La Forge?
It is too early to tell
if the nano-cortical fibers
performed their function.
I suspect none of the humans
will survive the process
but then... it's their
own fault, isn't it?
They never should
have come here.
What were they thinking?
They came looking for me.
Oh, humans are
so sentimental.
I betrayed them.
If they die,
I am responsible.
Why are you talking like that?
Is something wrong
with your programming?
Maybe I should
check your systems.
I do not want you
to check my systems.
I must resolve
these issues myself.
I think I made a mistake.
I don't believe
you can tolerate
the amount of emotion
I've given you.
Perhaps I should cut back
a little.
( gasps )
How's that?
I do not like it.
Then you prefer
to have more emotions?
Yes.
They give you pleasure?
Yes, please, I want more.
All right.
A little more...
for now.
Aren't you going
to thank me?
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
I just hope this helps
to clarify things for you.
I'm concerned about
my brother, Crosis.
I don't believe
he really wants
to be a part
of our great future.
Sir, metaphasic shielding
is losing integrity.
Can you stabilize it?
No. We won't be able
to stay in here
longer than another
three or four minutes.
Do we have
warp engines yet?
Last estimate was
another half hour.
Sir, I think
I have an idea.
I think it's possible we could
induce a solar fusion eruption
that would destroy
the Borg ship.
What?
We'd need to direct
a highly energetic particle beam
onto the sun's surface.
That should produce
a superfluid gas eruption.
If we target
the right spot
the eruption would
envelop the Borg ship.
How do you know
this will work?
I did my senior honors thesis
on solar dynamics.
Excuse me, sir but
this isn't the academy
and a student thesis is
a long way from a workable plan.
I've already configured
the tractor emitters
to create the particle beam
and I've located
the target point on the surface.
If her calculations are off
that eruption
could encompass us.
Well, I'll just have
to make sure
my calculations
are accurate, Lieutenant.
Let's do it.
Yes, sir.
The target area
of the photosphere
is destabilizing.
Pressure wave expansion
is accelerating.
Subsurface fusion
has been initiated.
An eruption is forming
on the surface.
She did it.
The Borg ship
has been destroyed, sir.
CRUSHER:
Helm, take us back
to the planet
full impulse.
Aye, sir.
Well done, Taitt.
You're killing him.
He won't survive
another session.
I did not come for him.
I came for you.
( groaning softly )
Data, it's not too late.
If you remove the fibers,
then Geordi might yet recover.
That would not
be possible.
Why? Because Lore
tells you so?
It is for
the greater good.
Good?
Data, isn't good and bad,
right and wrong
a function of your
ethical program?
That is correct.
And what does
that program tell you
about what you're doing
to Geordi?
About what you and Lore
are doing to the Borg?
It tells you that
these things are wrong
doesn't it, Data?
So how can actions
that are wrong
lead to a greater good?
You are attempting
to confuse me.
No, you're not confused, Data.
You're sensing the truth.
Your ethical program
is fighting the
negative emotions
that Lore
is sending you.
Ah, Captain.
Thank you so much
for joining us.
You are going to
assist me...
in a most important ceremony.
We can use the
environmental
control ducts
to get into
the compound.
They should lead us
to the detention area.
We'll have
to move fast.
If we need to stun
one of the guards
the Borg will know right away
if he's been hurt.
When they realize
your escape route
may be compromised.
I guess we'll have
to take that chance.
Good luck,
Commander.
It's time to put aside
all doubts, brother.
It's time to close
the door on the past
and commit yourself
to the great work
that lies ahead of us.
I need to know
I can count on you.
As proof,
I want you to kill Picard.
No... that would
be wrong.
I didn't think you'd
be able to do it.
You've spent
too many years
among humans.
Hold him.
I've asked
many sacrifices of you--
sacrifices I knew
were necessary
in order to build
a better future.
I want you to know
that I ask no more of you
than I am prepared
to give myself.
I am willing to make the
greatest sacrifice of all...
... my own... dear brother.
Good-bye, Data.
No!
( Borg yelling )
( yelling continues )
( grunting )
( grunting and groaning )
Lore.
You should be careful
with that, brother.
Someone could get hurt.
What are you doing?
I've got a way
out of here.
I'm willing to forget
what happened back there--
take you with me.
We don't need anyone else.
We're brothers.
I'll give you the chip
our father made.
It contains much more
than just emotions.
It has memories.
Memories... our father
wanted you to have.
( groans )
Lore, I must
deactivate you now.
( speaking haltingly ):
Without me
you will never
feel emotion again.
I know...
but you leave me
no other choice.
( beeping )
( voice slowing ):
I... love you...
brother.
Good-bye, Lore.
What about Geordi and Troi?
The Enterprise
is in orbit.
I had them
beamed aboard.
Lore is no longer
functioning, sir.
He must be disassembled
so that he is
no longer a threat.
Welcome back, Data.
Thank you, sir.
What made you change
your mind, Hugh?
Perhaps my encounter
with the Enterprise
affected me more
than I realized.
What will you do now?
( sighing )
I don't know.
We can't go back
to the Borg collective
and we no longer
have a leader here.
I'm not sure that's true.
Perhaps in time,
we will learn
to function as individuals
and work together as a group.
Good luck, Hugh.
Good-bye.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47025.4.
We have returned
to Federation space
and are en route
to Starbase 295.
Mr. La Forge remains
under Dr. Crusher's care.
( door chiming )
Enter.
Hi, Data.
I wanted to let you know
that Dr. Crusher says
I'll be able to return
to duty soon.
I am... relieved
that the injuries
I inflicted on you
are not permanent.
What's that?
This is the chip
my father created for me
so that I could
experience emotion.
I had it removed
from Lore's body
before he was
dismantled.
Does it work?
No.
I am pleased to say
it was damaged
when I was forced
to fire on Lore.
Pleased?
Data, you've wanted emotions
your whole life.
Yes.
But emotions are responsible
for what I did to you.
I would never risk
letting that
happen again.
My friendship with you
is too important to me.
Data, I wouldn't be
very much of a friend
if I let you give up
on a lifelong dream
now would I?
Maybe someday...
when you're ready.
♪♪