Aw!
( door chimes )
Enter. Enter!
Worf, they're going to be
here any minute.
I am having problems.
If I didn't
know you better
I'd say that you were
procrastinating.
Klingons do not
procrastinate.
It is a tactical delay.
You have to spend
about five minutes
greeting the Iyaarans
when they get here
and maybe an hour
making small talk
at this reception.
I'm the one who
has to escort them
around the ship for
the next three days.
I do not enjoy
these diplomatic situations.
It's all part of
being in Starfleet.
There.
I do not see
why it is necessary
to wear these
ridiculous uniforms.
Protocol.
They look like dresses.
That is an incredibly
outmoded and sexist attitude.
I'm surprised at you.
Besides,
you look good in a dress.
PICARD:
What's keeping them?
Ah, you're just in time.
They're about to disembark.
Ambassador Loquel,
Ambassador Byleth,
I am Captain Picard.
Welcome on board
the Enterprise.
It is our pleasure
to be here, Captain.
It is an honor
to be the site
of the first
cultural exchange
between
the Iyaaran people
and the Federation.
Yes, the next seven days
should prove
most illuminating.
Allow me
to introduce Voval.
He'll be taking you back
to our homeworld.
How do you do?
I'm looking forward
very much
to meeting with
the Premier of Iyar.
There will be a reception
held in your honor
when you will meet
the rest of my senior staff.
I, of course, shall be
on my way to your homeworld
but I shall be leaving you
in the safe hands
of my most
experienced officers.
Lieutenant Worf,
of the Klingon Empire
is my Head of Security.
He will be in charge
of your safety
while you're on board.
Counselor Deanna Troi,
of the planet Betazed
will be your personal
liaison officer,
Ambassador Loquel.
Ambassador, it's
an honor to meet you.
Would you like to see
your quarters
before we attend
the reception?
Please.
Ambassador Byleth,
this is Commander
William Riker,
my First Officer,
from the planet Earth.
He has been
assigned to you.
I want this one.
Well, Commander Riker
is a skilled diplomat
with wide experience
in interspecies contact.
I'm sure, I'm sure.
But I have decided.
I want this...
Lieutenant Worf.
Well, that will be,
uh... just fine.
Mr. Worf?
Yes.
Yes, Ambassador, it
would be my pleasure...
Yes, yes,
enough of that.
Show me
to my quarters.
This way.
Good luck.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
( quiet conversation )
So, first thing
tomorrow
I thought I'd take
you on a tour
of the operational
centers
and residential decks
of the ship.
And then we could
spend some time
discussing the cultural
underpinnings of your society.
Are you going to eat?
Excuse me?
You have no food
on your plate.
Are you going
to eat?
Oh, um, actually,
I was waiting
till we got to
the desserts.
Desserts--
what is this?
Oh, it's something we eat
after the main course.
It's usually very sweet.
It's usually
very bad for you.
We eat it purely
for pleasure.
If you ask me,
it's the best
part of any meal.
My people eat
only for nourishment.
Oh, well, um, let
me introduce you
to some of my favorites.
This is peach cobbler
with whipped cream,
Tarvokian powder cake,
and this is my favorite--
Ktarian chocolate puff.
I don't know exactly
what's inside
but I think it's made
with 17 varieties
of chocolate.
That is...
Delicious?
Delicious.
Ambassador, I think
we're going to get
along very well.
Shall we?
This is unacceptable.
I am sorry you do
not care for our...
Bring me new food.
I require a higher protein
and enzymatic content.
Ambassador...
Yes?
it's the custom,
usually,
in a situation
like this
for us to serve
ourselves.
It's called a buffet.
Bring me new food.
Ambassador...
Doctor, it is all right.
I am happy to
bring more food.
( groaning )
How is your diplomatic
assignment progressing?
Fine.
I have heard
that in moments
of diplomatic tension
it is often helpful
to find elements
of commonality.
Ambassador Byleth is demanding,
temperamental and rude.
You share all of those
qualities in abundance.
Perhaps you should
try to build on
your similarities.
So...
I understand
that your homeworld
has some of the most spectacular
crystal formations
in this sector.
( grunts )
Is there any place
in particular
that you would recommend
I visit while I'm there?
No.
Well, I, um...
What's our ETA?
17 hours, 32 minutes.
I think I'll go update
my itinerary.
( alarms beeping )
What happened?
There has been
a system-wide power failure.
What's the cause?
We have entered an
energy disruption field.
I do not recognize
the configuration.
Attitude controls failing.
There is an M-Class planet
in this system.
Can we reach it?
I will try.
Inertial dampeners
are off-line.
Life-support
is failing.
Entering
the planet's atmosphere.
Velocity dropping.
Thermal shields
at full power.
Prepare for impact.
( thunder cracks )
Voval.
( groaning )
( thunder rumbling )
( grunting )
Voval, try not to move.
You may have a concussion.
Picard to Enterprise.
Do you read me?
( static )
Too much interference.
There's a structure of some kind
and... some energy readings
about two kilometers
south of here.
Voval, I'm going
to try and get help.
Do you understand?
Now, try to stay
conscious
and don't leave
the shuttle.
There's some kind
of plasma energy
out on the surface.
I'll be back
as soon as I can.
( gasps )
The engineering section
encompasses 12 decks
of the secondary hull.
Deck 42 contains
the antimatter
storage facility...
What is the mass-flow rate
of the antimatter
replenishment stream
to the containment pods?
Excuse me?
The antimatter
replenishment rate--
what is it?
I am not certain...
Perhaps there is
somebody here who
does know the answer.
You!
Are you smarter than this one?
( clears throat )
Why do you ask?
Never mind.
I wish to see
the Bussard collectors.
Take me to them.
This way.
( chuckling )
This deck is devoted mainly
to stellar cartography,
biological research
and astrophysics.
We have over 1,000
people on board...
Are you sure you don't want
some of this...
this papalla juice?
No, thank you.
I'm still recovering
from all those
desserts last night.
Are you sure?
It is very delicious.
I'm sure.
Please. Please.
You've... you've
been so kind.
Please.
Yum.
Next, we're going
to deck eight,
which is really
interesting
because it's not
really finished.
It's sort of
a multipurpose...
Sometimes when we need
an extra lab or...
Ambassador?
What is this?
It's a child.
Child?!
Children are our offspring.
They're our young.
They grow into adults
over a period of many years.
They grow into beings like us.
Offspring.
Ambassador, I'm curious.
How does your
species procreate?
Postcellular compounding.
We emerge from the
natal pod fully grown.
I see.
Do you have a name?
Eric.
Do you like... dessert?
May I give Eric
some dessert?
That sounds like
a wonderful idea.
Come on, Eric.
( groans )
( beeping )
Is someone there?
Who's there?
What do you want?
Who are you?
Shh.
No, wait! Stop!
There was someone else
in the shuttlecraft with me.
The pilot-- he's injured.
He needs your help.
He's dead.
( door locking )
PICARD:
Hello.
Smells good.
Thank you.
( groaning )
This is a Terellian
cargo freighter, isn't it?
Is this your ship?
You one of the crew?
No.
I was a passenger.
We crashed.
How many people survived?
Were you the only one?
Well, you're certainly
not a Terellian,
unless you've lost
two of your arms.
What's your name?
I'm Jean-Luc Picard.
I'm a Starfleet officer.
Anna.
Anna?
Are there other people
on this planet?
How long have you been here?
I don't know.
You can't see
the sun from here.
I've lost track of all time.
What was the date
when you crashed?
Stardate 40812.
Seven years.
Years?
Anna...
Anna, wait a minute.
Seven years?
I... I thought one...
maybe two.
How could it be seven?
Anna...
Anna, listen to me.
Listen.
On the shuttle,
there is a lot of equipment
that will have survived
the crash.
We can use it
to contact Starfleet.
They'll send a ship for us.
We can leave.
Leave?
Yes.
Both of us.
Now, if you will help me
to get to the shuttle...
Oh!
Don't move.
It's bad.
Don't worry.
I won't move.
You have
three broken ribs.
The restrictor device
will hold the
bones in place.
Let them...
Hmm...
Let them knit?
It's been so long
since I talked to anyone.
I used to talk...
to myself.
But then I thought
that it might mean
I was crazy.
So I... I stopped talking.
It'll be a while
before you can walk.
Then, perhaps you could go
to the shuttle
and bring the equipment
back here.
I can do that.
Good.
Go into the cockpit.
Look for a small com panel
in the instrument array.
See if you can remove it.
Bring it back here.
Don't move.
I'll be back.
I am going to kill him
with my bare hands.
I will take him
by the throat
and rip out
his esophagus...
Worf!
I have failed in my mission,
Commander.
I am clearly a bad diplomat.
For the sake of the ship
and the Federation
I request
reassignment.
Denied.
But, Commander, these Iyaarans
are arrogant, irritating.
They cannot be reasoned with.
Ambassador Loquel
is quite pleasant.
I will admit, though,
he's a little unusual.
RIKER:
What have you been able
to find out about him so far?
Well, he seems preoccupied
with recreation.
I've spent more time
in Ten-Forward
in the last two days
than I have in
the past two months.
And he's obsessed with food,
especially chocolate.
You must be
in heaven.
To be honest,
he's testing even my limits.
You see? You see?
They are insane!
Worf.
You've been very patient
with Ambassador Byleth,
and that's good,
but maybe it's time
to let him know
that some behavior
is unacceptable to us.
I think it's all right
to suggest limits
for the Ambassador.
Aw...
Perhaps we should
loosen things up
a little bit--
meet in a less
official capacity.
How about a friendly
game of poker?
( door rattling )
What are you doing?
You should be in bed.
Anna, why was this door
locked from the outside?
For your protection.
From what?
There are dangerous
animals here.
Come sit down.
Look, I have
the com panel.
Good.
It wasn't easy.
I had to force it out
of the equipment bay.
If we can boost
the out...
( groans )
...the output field,
I might be able
to send a
distress signal.
Something seems
to be wrong with it.
What's the matter?
Why, this transmitter module
has been totally destroyed.
How could that happen?
It looks as though
it's been hit by a phaser blast.
I used a phaser
to cut it free.
Maybe I accidentally
damaged it.
Well, you can fix it,
can't you?
No.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Anna...
we will get out of here.
It's not going to be easy
but we must
work together.
I can't believe I did that--
that I damaged our only chance.
I've waited for so long.
At first, I had hope
that I would be rescued.
I kept setting up
microfusion flares
and looking up at the sky
and waiting for someone
to come and take me away.
But it never happened.
There's a...
a precipice near here.
I used to go there
and I'd stare down at the gorge
and I'd think...
"I can just step over the edge
and end it all."
And then I realized
that it was the hope
that was driving me crazy.
That I had to accept
I would never get out of here.
Anna, no matter
how long it takes
we will get out of here.
I knew
from the moment I saw you
that you were here
to save me.
I'll do anything
you want.
Just...
don't leave me.
I don't ever want
to be alone again.
I love you.
( thunder cracks )
I found some coltayin roots.
They're not much to look at,
but they taste good.
What are you doing?
You're going
to hurt yourself.
No, no, no,
it's all right.
I'm just trying to dislodge
this power cell.
Nearly got it.
There.
No, no, it's all right.
The energy relays
are corroded
but I think it should be able
to hold one more charge.
If I can regenerate this
then I may be able
to reactivate
the shuttlecraft's engines.
Well, I'd say
this is cause
for celebration.
I may still have some
Terellian spices around here.
And I'll boil up
these roots
and make us
a nice broth.
Ah, that sounds delightful.
Mm-hmm.
If we ever do get out of here,
will you promise
to show me
this starship of yours--
this Enterprise?
Of course.
Anna, would you pass me
that tricorder?
I'm going to try to repair
these energy relays.
I meant
what I said before.
I do love you.
Anna...
I'm very grateful to you
for saving my life,
and I think that you are
a very warm
and compassionate woman,
and I feel a great sympathy
for what you've been through
alone here on this planet,
but I don't think that you
can really be in love with me.
How can you say that?
Of course I love you.
No. I'm the first person
you've seen in seven years.
I'm bringing you the hope
of leaving this place.
Don't you think that...
you could possibly be
just a little confused
right now?
So... you're not
attracted to me?
I think
it's a little premature.
We hardly know anything
about each other.
I understand...
and I'm sorry
if I made you uncomfortable.
Ah... no harm done.
( tricorder beeping )
It's going to take at least
a couple of hours
to charge this cell.
Then, as soon as it's done,
we should get it over
to the shuttlecraft immediately.
This cell casing is already
beginning to break down.
Anna?
We are going
to get out of here.
Bet is ten.
That's to you, Ambassador.
I will see the bet...
and, uh, raise ten.
I'm in for 20.
I'm in...
and I raise 20.
You are... bluffing.
Excuse me, Ambassador.
Those are my chips.
You are in error.
Those chips are mine.
I saw you take two chips
from my pile.
You would dare
to accuse me of stealing?
Yes.
You are lying
because you are
losing the game.
I am losing
because you have been
cheating all along.
Wait a minute.
Calm down.
Even if I were cheating,
how would a plodding
animal like you know it?
You are an insulting,
pompous fool.
And if you were not
an ambassador
I would disembowel you
right here!
Do not let my title
inhibit you, Klingon.
( groans )
Yes.
Good.
( grunts )
Stop!
Mr. Worf,
that is an order!
Wonderful.
Very good.
Thank you, Lieutenant Worf.
I think I understand now.
That was a very
effective demonstration.
What?
If you'll excuse me,
I would like to document
this experience.
This power cell is ready.
We should take it
over to the shuttle.
No. We can't leave
right now.
Why not?
The plasma storms
are too strong.
It's dangerous.
Wait a few hours,
then we can go.
We don't have a few hours.
I told you,
this cell is already
beginning to degenerate.
Jean-Luc,
it's a difficult journey.
The restriction field
will make it very hard
for you to walk.
I'm feeling
very much better.
In fact...
I don't intend to go on
using this any longer.
No!
You can't remove it yet.
There's no pain.
( inhales deeply )
It would appear I don't have
any broken ribs after all.
Jean-Luc...
What's going on?
Why are you trying
to keep me here?
Please...
I love you.
Why are you keeping me
locked in this freighter?
You say that there are
wild animals out there
but I haven't heard or seen
a single one of them.
Jean-Luc...
What about
the com panel?
You said you damaged
it when you were
cutting it out of
the shuttle. Did you?
You see, I find it
hard to believe
that you would destroy
the one piece
of equipment that could get you
out of here after seven years.
And what was this
really for, hmm?
To keep me immobilized?
I was afraid...
I didn't want you
to leave me.
So it was necessary
to keep me captive?
I was scared.
I wanted you to stay...
to love me.
I'm going to go look
for the shuttle myself.
No!
Anna...
Don't fight me!
Anna, no!
You should love me now.
We're together.
We depend
on each other.
I know more about you.
Love me.
Anna, stop!
I've failed.
You don't love me.
It's over.
Anna...
Anna?
Anna, where
are you going?
MAN:
Hello?
Is anyone in there?
Yes, inside here!
Hello!
Inside the freighter!
The door is
on the opposite side!
Over here!
The door's over here!
Voval.
I thought you were dead.
Dead?
Yes. There's a woman
living here.
She told me that she'd
been to the shuttle.
She said that
she saw you dead.
Yes, that is
understandable.
When my species is injured
our metabolic rate
slows until our body
can heal itself.
This state could easily
be mistaken for death.
I see.
When you did not
return to the shuttle
I intended to track you.
Surface conditions
made it very difficult.
So cold.
I saw someone
running away from here.
Was it the woman?
Yes.
Why did she leave
the shelter?
She was upset.
Do you think
she may harm herself?
There's a dangerous
precipice near here.
She was headed
in that direction.
It's possible.
Then we should go
find her.
You stay here, keep warm.
I'll go and look for her.
We will go together.
PICARD:
Anna!
Captain, this ridge
extends for a kilometer
in either direction.
We can search it
twice as fast
if we separate.
Anna!
Anna.
Anna...
Stay away from me.
You don't have to do this.
I found Voval,
the shuttle pilot.
He's still alive.
He can help us
get away from here.
( sobbing ):
I don't care.
I'll jump,
unless you promise
to love me.
No.
No, I won't promise.
You have been manipulating me,
haven't you?
Jean-Luc,
what are you saying?
The necklace...
it broke.
I saw it in the cargo freighter
on the floor by the fire.
I left it there.
Now it's around
your neck.
It's whole! How?
Tell me you love me.
I must know.
Where's Voval?
Isn't it convenient
that he arrived
moments after you left?
That he insisted
that I come here
to look for you?
That I find you
here on the ledge
ready to jump?
That's very good timing,
don't you think?
Jean-Luc...
Are you and Voval
working together?
He is the only one who could
have brought you the necklace.
Tell me about your love,
or I'll jump.
Go ahead.
Why don't you do it?
It's a...
long way down.
Must be 200 meters.
You'd die instantly,
if that's what you want,
but I don't think
that it really is.
I have failed.
Failed?!
Voval, what is going on?!
My name is Ambassador Voval.
Ambassador?!
My mission was
to study human intimacy--
specifically the concept
you call "love."
In our study
of your culture
we did not understand
certain concepts,
so we sent three representatives
to study them...
to experience them.
But why did you believe
that bringing me here
would give you a better
understanding of love?
Several years ago,
we discovered the remains
of the Terellian freighter
on this planet.
The ship contained logs
written
by a single survivor--
a human woman.
That was our first contact
with the human culture.
The woman lived alone here
for seven years
until another human
crashed on this planet--
a human male.
And the man was injured
and she nursed him
back to health...
and they fell in love.
In the logs,
she described many concepts
we found difficult
to understand.
Pleasure, antagonism, love.
These were alien to us.
We wished to experience them
for ourselves.
Ambassador Loquel was sent
to experience pleasure.
Byleth was sent
to experience antagonism.
And I was sent
to experience love.
Was this wrong?
( sighs )
Let me just say that...
we would not take
such a direct approach.
Ambassador,
I have to tell you
that in my culture
what you have done would
be considered a crime.
Crime?
Well... we'll talk
about it later.
For now, I think we should
get off this planet.
Am I right in assuming that
the damage to the shuttle
is not as bad
as it seems?
That is correct.
We can leave at any time.
I think that now
would be quite nice.
You look a little sore.
Lieutenant Worf
was kind enough
to engage me in 11 hours
of holodeck battle exercises.
11 hours?
Yes. I learned
a great deal
about the concept
of antagonism.
It was... excruciating.
Counselor, these are
bioenzymatic supplements
my people
consume for food.
I'm afraid you'll find
they are not as delicious
as your chocolate.
After the past few days
I could use something
a little bland.
Good-bye, Ambassador.
Fascinating species.
Indeed.
Thank you, Captain.
This has been
an enlightening experience.
For me as well,
Ambassador.
I am sorry if our diplomatic
methods offended you.
No, on the contrary,
I found your
approach intriguing.
We humans tend to take
a rather balanced
approach towards life--
never too much,
never too little--
and it's very nice
to find a culture
that is willing
to take an experience
to its furthest extreme.
Good-bye, Captain.
Ambassador.