RIKER:
Geordi, have you found it yet?
Not yet.
( loud hissing )
I'm starting
to get some fumes!
Ammonia... chlorine,
potassium chloride.
( coughing )
Oh, I can feel
the heat from here.
There it is.
RIKER:
How far?
About ten meters
up the ODN line.
Boy, it's hot.
I'd say over 2,000 degrees.
I'm going in.
( loud rumbling )
( clanking )
( beeping )
( hissing )
We're okay.
I've activated the emergency
suppression system.
DR. CRUSHER:
All his vital functions
are completely normal.
The interface unit is operating
within expected parameters.
Why did he start coughing
when he went through the gases?
DR. CRUSHER:
Psychosomatic response.
I feel like
I'm actually here...
I mean, there--
in the Jefferies tube.
It's funny--
when I saw the smoke,
I couldn't help but cough.
No one has ever reported so
complete a sensory experience.
The interface is
perfect for Geordi
because his visor inputs
allow the probe
to transmit information directly
into his cerebral cortex.
It looks like this
is going to work.
Geordi, I'd like
to get the probe
out of the Jefferies tube
onto the Launch Bay
before we reach
Marijne VII.
Will do.
Wait a minute.
Something's wrong.
I can't get
my left leg to work.
What is it?
The probe is designed
to respond
to any movement
Geordi intends to make.
When his brain sends
a message to move his leg,
the interface should move
the probe instead.
Apparently, the tactile
sensors are too low.
I will increase
the input.
There it goes.
I'm on my way down.
Why the bodysuit?
It provides tactile sensations
so that Geordi can feel
he's in the same
environment as the probe.
Geordi,
what's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm seeing my reflection
in a panel.
I forgot what
a handsome guy I am.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47215.5:
We are responding
to a distress call
from the science vessel Raman,
which is apparently trapped
inside the turbulent atmosphere
of an unusual gas giant planet.
We will use an experimental
interface probe
in our attempt
to rescue it.
I have reviewed
the vessel's mission plans.
The Raman was to descend
to the lower atmosphere
11,000 kilometers below
its current position.
The crew was to sample
the atmosphere at that level
and then return
to a safer orbit.
Something must have
happened down there.
Maybe the shields failed
or they had some kind of
inversion reaction
in the nacelles.
Any life signs?
LA FORGE:
Our biosensors are useless.
There's too much interference
in the atmosphere.
Their crew might
still be alive.
There's no way we can
tell from up here.
Will the probe be able
to transmit through
that interference?
The probe sends information
via a focused particle beam.
It should be able to cut
through the interference.
But we may have
to operate the probe
at close to tolerance levels.
Hmm.
Will your nervous system
be able to handle
that much sensory input?
We've already tested
the interface
at about 70% of tolerance.
We shouldn't have
any trouble going higher.
The safety override will
kick in at about 98% tolerance
and that will disengage
the interface.
WORF:
Captain, I am receiving
a transmission
from Starfleet Command--
Admiral Holt.
In my Ready Room.
The seven people on that ship
are our first priority.
Is the probe ready
for launch?
Yes, sir.
Send it directly
to the aft section
of the Raman through
the secondary airlock.
That way it should put it
just one bulkhead away
from the Bridge.
I'll interface
with the probe
as soon as it's ready
and take it the rest
of the way from there.
Make it so.
Hello, Marcus.
Jean-Luc.
How's life on DS3?
We're hosting
this year's palio.
The, uh, Ferengi have already
been accused of trying
to bribe the Breen pilot
into throwing the race.
( chuckles softly )
Well, there's nothing
unusual about that.
Nothing at all.
I wish I could say
that I was calling
just to catch up on things.
Nine days ago,
the Hera left here
on a routine courier mission.
We were in contact with it
for five of those days.
Then the ship disappeared
without a trace.
The Hera?
I'm afraid so.
The Excelsior and the Noble
have been retracing its course
for the last 72 hours.
Nothing.
I'm going to keep them
at it for another 72,
but to be honest,
I don't think another week
would make any difference.
I'll inform
Commander La Forge.
( sighs )
( door opens and closes )
Mr. Data, I'd like a word
with Commander La Forge.
Aye, sir.
I will be on the Bridge.
Geordi, I've just
spoken with Starfleet.
The Hera is missing.
Missing?
My mother?
Captain La Forge
has disappeared
along with the rest
of her crew.
WOMAN:
I saw your father last week,
and your sister about
ten days before that.
I decided I missed
my favorite son.
Your only son, Ma.
You're going to have
to see the Hera again.
We have a lot of
new faces on board,
including a chief engineer
who juices up the nacelles
every chance she gets.
I think she's the best
technician in the fleet.
Okay, second best.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were...
Don't worry about it.
Maybe you should meet her.
We're going to be
in the same sector next week.
Take a shuttle over
and I'll introduce you.
My mother's always trying
to find me a wife.
MRS. LA FORGE:
...I'll see you at your
father's birthday party.
Remember,
if you talk to him,
it's a surprise.
This came in
about three weeks ago.
I never got back to her.
Geordi, the probe has entered
the planet's atmosphere
and I'm ready to take it
onto the ship.
If you would like to take
a couple of days off,
I'll run the interface.
The interface is calibrated
specifically to
my visor's inputs.
It would take you at least
ten hours to convert it
and those crewmen
down there can't wait.
The interface doesn't have
to be fully compatible.
I could run it right now.
I wouldn't have the same
control that you have,
but it would still work.
Forget it.
I'm the best person
for the job
and there's no reason why
we shouldn't proceed as planned.
The Hera is reason enough.
The Hera is missing,
that's all.
Until I hear
something different,
my mother just might as well
have taken the crew
on an unscheduled holiday.
Let's go.
Captain, the probe
is through the airlock
and in position
aboard the Raman.
Picard to Commander Data,
report.
We are ready to bring
the interface online, sir.
PICARD:
Proceed.
Activating
the remote sensors.
Initiating interface... now.
Vital signs are normal.
Geordi, how do you feel?
Fine.
DATA:
Do you have visual contact?
Not yet.
Data, turn up
the input sensors.
I'm not seeing anything.
DATA:
Acknowledged.
Okay, I can see,
but no colors.
Increasing signal strength
to 75% of tolerance.
Ah... that's better.
DR. CRUSHER:
Your pulse has gone up.
Your nervous system probably has
to get used to the input levels.
I'm excited,
that's all, Doctor.
This is like being on
a roller coaster.
Or a first date.
I'm all right.
I'll be the judge of that.
If your heart rate
gets too high,
we're going to
disconnect you.
Understood.
It's a mess in here.
There must be a breach
in the hull someplace.
I'm picking up
atmospheric gases
in the corridor.
Methane and ammonia
primarily.
That break in the hull might
even be on the Bridge itself.
I'm heading
towards the Bridge.
I found someone.
DATA:
What is your position?
About 12 meters
up the main corridor.
He's trapped under some conduit
from the bulkhead.
I can't move it.
I'm going to need more power
to the tractor beam.
DR. CRUSHER:
Go to 80% of tolerance, Data.
No higher.
He's dead.
Data...
that door at the end
of this corridor.
What's it lead to?
DATA:
A magnetic Storage Bay.
If there was a break
in the Bridge,
that'd be
the safest place to go.
( air hissing )
( beeping )
( grunting )
Data, give me a phaser burst.
Narrow focus,
level four intensity.
I found them.
They're dead...
all of them.
There's a fire in here.
( yelling in pain )
Data, disconnect.
What happened?
Geordi?
I don't know.
My hands.
They're burned.
PICARD:
How did this happen?
DR. CRUSHER: There was
some kind of energy discharge
in the interface suit.
But shouldn't the safety
overrides have prevented that?
Yes, but I have a theory
why they didn't.
The tolerance levels
of the interface
were set extremely high.
I think Geordi's neural response
to the input was so strong
that it created
a feedback loop.
The sensors
that were transmitting
the sensation of heat
to my hands
must have overloaded.
The crew of
the Raman are dead.
I would like to retrieve them
and their vessel,
but not if it means putting
Geordi's safety at risk.
If we turn down the sensory
input on the probe,
I should be fine.
Seven people lost their lives
down there, Captain.
We should at least
retrieve the information
they were collecting.
Doctor?
If we operate the interface
at lower input levels,
I'd say the risk
is acceptable.
Picard to Riker.
Riker here.
We will proceed
with the probe.
We'll have to take it
into the Raman's
Auxiliary Control Room.
Their Bridge is
too badly damaged.
How long before you
have it in position?
RIKER:
A couple of hours.
We have to cut through
the bulkhead.
Acknowledged.
Well, it looks like
you'll have time to recuperate.
Yeah...
There's something
I've got to do anyway.
How are you, Dad?
As well as
could be expected...
under the circumstances.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I spoke with your sister
this morning.
She said she'll be in touch
with you in a few days.
Right now,
she's pretty upset.
The service...
for the Hera will
probably be on Vulcan.
Most of the crew
were from there.
But your sister and I...
want to have a private ceremony.
Dad...
don't you think everybody's
jumping the gun here?
Last I heard,
there were still two starships
out there looking for them.
They found no debris,
no residual
warp distortion...
And no ship.
Not yet, but that
doesn't mean they won't.
Starfleet is considering
the Hera lost.
The search isn't much more
than a formality at this point.
Geordi...
your mother's gone.
Yeah, well, you can
think that if you want,
but until I see
some hard evidence,
I'm not going
to give up hope.
All right, Geordi.
Call me if you need anything.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hey, Data.
Still working?
No. I have completed the
adjustments to the interface.
I am now waiting
for Commander Riker
to finish
moving the probe.
Do you need
to be comforted?
No. I was just passing by.
I was wondering
what you were up to.
I am using the time to catch up
on my study of poetry.
LA FORGE: Data,
there's nothing on the screen.
That is not
entirely correct.
While it is true
the display is currently blank,
this... emptiness
has a poetic meaning.
Therefore, it cannot be
considered "nothing" as such.
Says who?
The ancient Doosodarians.
Much of their poetry contains
such "lacunae" or empty spaces.
Often these pauses measured
several days in length,
during which
poet and audience
were encouraged
to fully acknowledge
the emptiness of
the experience.
I can remember a few lectures
from Starfleet Academy
that seemed that way.
Are you certain you do not wish
to talk about your mother?
Why would you say that?
You are no doubt feeling
emotional distress
as a result of
her disappearance.
While you claim to be
"just passing by,"
that is most likely an excuse
to start a conversation
about this
uncomfortable subject.
Am I correct?
No, Data.
Sometimes "just passing by"
means "just passing by."
Hmm.
Then I apologize for
my premature assumption.
This particular poem
has a lacuna of 47 minutes.
You may experience the emptiness
with me if you wish.
Thanks.
( sighing )
You know, Data,
maybe you gave up
a little too easily.
I do not understand.
Well, when I said
"just passing by"
means "just passing by,"
I really
didn't mean it.
Then my initial
assumption was correct.
You do wish to speak
of your mother.
Am I crazy to think
that she's still alive?
Your sanity
is not in question.
However,
your evaluation
of the available
information is biased.
She's a starship captain.
She's gotten herself
into and out of
impossible
situations before.
Why should this
be any different?
Disappearances fitting
the profile of the Hera
have rarely ended with the safe
recovery of ship and crew.
Well, that makes me
feel much better.
( sighs )
Look, I'm...
I'm sorry, Data.
I didn't mean
to snap at you.
I am not offended.
You are upset.
Your reactions
are not surprising.
It's just that if...
if she really is dead...
I don't know what
I'm going to do.
We're receiving
the probe's telemetry.
The input levels are currently
at 53% of tolerance.
That's too low, Data.
I won't be able
to do anything down there.
I want to start with as wide
margin of safety as possible.
We can adjust upward later.
Ready?
Go ahead.
Initiating interface.
( beeping )
( machinery powering up )
I can't see anything.
DATA:
I am increasing the input now.
LA FORGE: Yeah.
Yeah, that's better,
but I need more.
DATA:
Is this level sufficient?
Geordi?
Geordi, do you hear me?
Mom?
Mom, is it you?
Is it you?
Oh, I forgot, all you
can see is this probe.
Yes! It's me!
I'm... I'm actually
on the Enterprise.
I'm interfaced
with this probe.
Geordi, who are you
speaking to?
What are you seeing?
But is it really you?
Yes, Geordi.
It's Mom.
But how can that be?
I mean,
how is this possible?
There's no time
to explain.
We have to go down.
Down where?
The surface.
Geordi, report.
Hang on, Doctor.
Why? Why do we have to go
down to the surface?
We're dying.
We? The Hera?
You mean the Hera
is down there?
DR. CRUSHER: We're
disconnecting you right now!
No, wait!
We need your help.
I need your help.
Mom!
Geordi!
The cutoff has been
automatically activated.
( alarm beeping )
He's in neural shock.
DR. CRUSHER:
The sensory overload didn't
cause any permanent damage,
but I wouldn't want
to expose his brain
to that kind
of stimulus again.
Is there any indication what
caused this hallucination?
His brain functions
are normal.
I told you,
I wasn't hallucinating.
Geordi, I have analyzed
the probe's sensor logs.
There are no records to indicate
the presence of a living human
on board the Raman.
Well, she wasn't
exactly there.
Her ship is down
on the surface.
So, you believe
that what you saw
was some kind
of transmission?
Somehow she has managed
to communicate with me.
We have no indication of
a transmission of any kind.
Maybe I'm the only one
who can detect it
because I'm interfaced
with the probe.
The probe does allow Geordi
to sense quantum fluctuations,
subspace anomalies
and other phenomenon
not perceptible by
any other kind of sensor.
Granted, but how could he
perceive his mother visually
as if she were standing
there in the room?
I'm not sure, but I do know
that our brains weren't designed
to process the kind of sensory
information Geordi was getting.
When the brain receives
something it doesn't understand,
it interprets
the input as best it can--
sometimes as
a smell or a sound,
sometimes visually.
You see?
But, Geordi, I'm not
saying that your mother
was really communicating
with you.
I'm just trying
to give you a reason
why you might have
thought that she was.
Look, I'm telling you,
my mother's ship
is trapped down there
and-and we've got
to help them.
Geordi, the Hera's
last reported position
was 300 light-years away.
How could it end up here?
If the Hera
is on the surface,
its hull could not
possibly withstand
the pressure
of the atmosphere.
Well, at least let me go back
down there just to be sure.
I do not recommend that
he use the interface again.
The sensory overload
almost killed you.
I'll be all right.
No, no, I'm sorry, Geordi.
I'm not prepared
to risk your life.
Data, find another way
of salvaging the Raman.
I want an alternate
plan in two hours.
Geordi...
I'd like you to talk
to Counselor Troi.
( frustrated sigh )
She's expecting you.
What's your mother like,
Geordi?
If you think I'm going
to start talking
about my childhood,
Counselor, you're way off.
That's not what I asked.
Well... she's...
she's brilliant...
funny.
She's incredibly
perceptive.
She knows people.
Knows what they're all about
even before they open
their mouths.
She's always been that way.
She's...
she's a real good judge
of character.
When was the last time
you saw her?
About seven months ago
when she first took
command of the Hera.
I went to a party
she had for her crew.
She wanted me to
come over and see her,
but I was...
really busy at the time.
I mean, I suppose I
could have made the time
to go and see her,
but...
you know,
I just didn't think that...
I mean, you know, I...
I didn't think that...
You didn't think it would be
your last chance to see her.
That's not what
I was going to say.
I want to suggest
something.
Call it a theory,
all right?
All right.
You're worried about the
disappearance of your mother...
guilty that you didn't see her
when you had the chance,
so you're unwilling to consider
that she might be dead.
Your need to believe
she's alive is so strong
that it manifests itself
as a physical image.
Yes, but she told me
she's trapped on that planet,
that she's in danger.
Now, if this were
some sort of wish fulfillment,
don't you think
I'd be fantasizing her
safe and sound?
No, because that would be
the end of your fantasy.
You'd know
it wasn't true.
The more involved
and complicated
and unending
your story is,
the longer you can believe
your mother's still alive.
Yeah, well, that's
your theory, Counselor.
I've got one of my own.
I've been exploring
the possibility
of using a tractor beam to pull
the Raman from the atmosphere.
However, the high level
of interference
prevents a positive lock.
If we set up some sort
of relay system...?
That is my conclusion
as well, Commander--
two shuttlecraft staggered
between the Enterprise
and the Raman
with their shields adjusted
to refocus the tractor beam.
Can we get the shuttles
close enough without danger?
Mr. La Forge?
Sure... um... yeah.
As long as we keep them both
above the troposphere,
that'll be all right.
Then in that case...
LA FORGE:
But what about the Hera?
We'd be leaving
my mother and her crew
stranded on the planet.
Commander...
I've been thinking about this.
A couple of weeks ago,
I got a message from my mother.
She said she had
a new chief engineer
who had been experimenting
with the warp drive.
Now, I've seen the Hera.
It uses trionic initiators
in the warp coil.
They have a reputation
for strange side effects,
especially when you start
playing around with them.
There have been
reports of warp bubbles
and other subspace
deformations.
So, what if that's
what happened?
Not a warp bubble,
but a subspace funnel.
Connecting two points
through subspace?
Well, the Hera could have
accidentally created
a distortion that emptied out
right here at Marijne VII.
Why here?
Well, the Hera passed by this
planet just ten days ago.
Now, there's an awful lot
of subspace disturbance
in the atmosphere.
The ship could have accidentally
picked up some residual traces
that directed the funnel
right back here.
So the Hera's in one piece
somewhere out there?
Well, maybe
it's being surrounded
by some kind of warp field,
but who knows for how long?
Mr. La Forge,
do you have any evidence
to support this hypothesis?
Well, I did pick up some pretty
strange subspace readings
when I was interfaced
with the probe.
Geordi, that could
have been anything.
LA FORGE: Yeah, but I talked
to her, Commander.
She asked me to bring
the Raman closer to the planet.
Mr. Data,
is any of this possible?
Yes, sir.
However,
it is highly unlikely.
How unlikely?
Nearly impossible, sir.
( sighs )
Let's proceed
with the shuttle plan.
Captain...
Dismissed.
Mr. La Forge.
I want you to know that
I am not unsympathetic
to what you're
going through.
Your mother's
disappearance is tragic,
but I cannot risk
your safety
on the basis of
a dubious hypothesis.
Captain, if I'm right,
and there's just one chance in
a million that she's alive...
I'm sorry, Geordi.
My decision is made.
I understand, sir.
We'll be in position
to use the tractor beam
in less than an hour.
You didn't come all the way
down here to tell me that.
No, I didn't.
Geordi...
I may have seemed
a little harsh
about the situation
aboard the Raman.
I just don't like the idea
of one of my best officers
putting himself
in unnecessary danger.
I guess I feel like
I should be the one
to decide whether
it's unnecessary or not.
My mother died
when I was a baby.
All I had was pictures
and the stories that my father
used to tell me about her.
I begged him to tell
those stories--
over and over.
When I was five
and I went to school,
I started to tell my new
friends those same stories,
pretending that
she was alive.
Then I started believing
that she was alive--
that she had just
gone away...
but that she
was coming back.
The teacher
got wind of this.
She and my father
had this talk with me.
They told me it was important
to accept the fact
that my mother was dead
and that she wasn't
coming back
and all the hoping in
the world wouldn't make it so.
In my mind, that was the day
that my mother actually died.
I cried all that night,
but after that,
it started feeling better.
Your mother was dead.
There was proof.
There was a body and a funeral.
It was a reality.
Geordi...
If I could see a body
if there were wreckage,
I could accept it,
but my mother
has just disappeared
and now,
there's a possibility
that she is alive
and I'm not
going to quit.
Not yet.
( machinery powering up )
( beeping )
I suspected you would attempt
to operate the interface alone.
Did you?
I am familiar enough with
your behavior patterns
to predict certain...
decisions.
Well, I guess you know me
pretty well.
You are disobeying
the Captain.
I can't just sit back
and do nothing
when I know that my mother
may be down on that planet.
I cannot allow you to
endanger your well-being.
Data...
if I leave
without knowing for sure,
then I'll have to
live with that
for the rest of my life--
wondering if I left her to die.
I couldn't do that.
That's why
I've got to do this.
I could have you
confined to quarters
for the duration
of the mission.
If that's what you need
to do, Data, then do it,
because nothing
short of that
is going to stop me from
trying to save my mother.
What are you doing?
I will monitor the interface
and attempt to keep you safe.
I cannot have you
confined to quarters
for something
you have not yet done.
You know, we could both get
into a lot of trouble for this.
There is a high degree
of probability
that you are correct.
Thanks, Data.
However,
I do have a request.
Yeah? What's that?
I would ask you to
consider the possibility
that what you see
is not real.
I will.
I promise.
I am establishing
the interface.
LA FORGE:
Mom?
Hello, Geordi.
Mom.
How did you get here?
I'm not really
with you, Geordi.
I'm on my ship
on the surface.
We were pulled
into a warp funnel.
That's just
what I thought.
How are we
communicating?
We found a way to send
a subspace signal
that could cut through
the atmospheric interference.
DATA: Geordi, are you seeing
the image of your mother?
Yes, and she's just confirmed
everything I've been saying.
I am reading unusual subspace
energy in your vicinity
similar to what
the probe sensor recorded
the first time
you encountered your mother.
That's how she's
communicating with me.
It's the only kind of signal
they could send
that could cut through
the interference.
We need your help.
I've been thinking
about this.
I'm going to take the Raman
into a low stationary orbit
and initiate
an inverse warp cascade.
Why?
The subspace distortion
from the cascade
should reverse
the warp funnel.
Your ship will end up
right back where it started.
Geordi,
the atmosphere
becomes increasingly turbulent
the farther down you go.
You may not be able
to bring the Raman
close enough to the Hera
before being destroyed.
I have to try, Data.
We're running out of time.
Shields back online.
We're starting
our descent.
( sighs )
Thank God.
Thank God?
That you're alive
that I was right
about all of this.
I can't wait
to call Dad.
He and Ariana
had given up.
We're going home.
Well, eventually, yeah...
Data...
everything's fading
in and out.
I'm losing the interface.
The probe is descending
out of range.
You'll have to turn up the input
gain to maintain my connection.
We are already
at 75% of tolerance.
Data, you can turn it
all the way up to a 100
if you do it slowly enough--
give my nervous system
a chance to adjust.
That is theoretically true,
but even at this level of input,
you are already experiencing
dangerous neural feedback.
There are over 300 people
are on board the Hera, Data.
You and I are the only
chance they've got.
I will increase the gain
incrementally as you descend.
It's working.
When we are ready
to disconnect the interface,
we must allow enough time
to lower the input levels.
Otherwise, your nervous system
will go into shock
from the sudden drop in input.
Well, once I initiate
the warp cascade,
we can start
dropping the gain.
DATA:
Understood.
We'll be within
sensor range of the Hera
in a few minutes.
Mom...
I'm really sorry
I didn't get by to see you
a couple of weeks ago.
You were too busy
with work.
Yeah, well,
I'm sorry.
It won't
happen again.
( beeping )
Captain, the Raman is
descending toward the planet.
Geordi.
We are at 90% of tolerance.
My calculations show
you will reach 100% of tolerance
before you are
in range of the Hera.
Then we're going to have
to go beyond tolerance.
That would not be advisable.
You must cease your descent.
No, Geordi, don't.
Please.
Data... I'm taking
this ship down.
Now, if you don't boost the gain
past tolerance levels,
I'll lose the interface
when we go out of range
and my system
will go into shock.
Geordi, you are putting me
in a difficult position.
Please,
cease your descent.
I won't do it, Data.
You're going to have
to increase the tolerance.
Disengaging safety systems.
Going to full tolerance
levels... now.
Thank you, Data.
We're getting close.
Thank God.
PICARD:
Commander La Forge.
Yes, Captain.
Stop your descent.
Prepare to disengage
the interface.
I'm sorry, Captain,
but I can't do that.
Damn it, Geordi,
you're going to kill yourself.
If I come back now, my mother
and her entire crew will die.
I'm scanning
for your ship.
I'm not getting anything.
We're still
too far away.
No, not really.
I should be picking
something up by now.
I'm not finding anything.
There's no warp funnel...
no ship...
there's nothing there.
PICARD:
Doctor, report.
His neural synapses
are overloading.
He can't survive this.
Geordi,
what's happening to you?
Reverse... tractor beam.
DATA:
Reversing tractor beam.
( panting )
( electrical crackling )
( flames roaring )
What are you?
You're killing us.
We must go down.
PICARD:
Geordi...
what's happening? Report.
You're... you're trapped?
Is there any way
that we can disconnect him?
If we take him off
too abruptly,
he'll go into neural shock.
Caught on the ship?
Reduce the input gradually
and still get him out
before it's too late.
Are you saying that you killed
the Raman's crew?
Perhaps we could deceive
his neural receptors.
Deceive them?
By feeding them
the sensory information
recorded from his early
experiences with the probe.
We could disconnect
the interface
and still maintain
the input levels.
We could then lower them
in a controlled manner.
What do you want?
Like a decompression tank.
Let's try it.
LA FORGE:
It was an accident...
Captain, I have to take the ship
into the lower atmosphere.
Explain.
As I understand it,
when the Raman got close
to the planet,
it accidentally picked up
some life-forms
that live
in the lower atmosphere--
subspace beings of some kind--
intelligent.
When the ship went back
into a higher orbit,
the beings were trapped.
How do you know all this?
One of them can
communicate with me.
It must have read my thoughts
through the probe interface
and took the form
of my mother
to try to talk me into taking
the ship closer to the surface.
Are these beings responsible
for the death
of the Raman's crew?
LA FORGE: Yes, but I don't
think it was on purpose.
They probably tried
communicating with them
the same way they're
communicating with me--
by directly accessing
their thoughts.
It must have been
fatal to the crew.
I guess the interface
is what protected me.
I have to take
them back, Captain.
They can't survive
so far up in the atmosphere.
I'll turn the ship around
and come back
just as soon as I'm...
( groaning )
Geordi, what's happening?
LA FORGE: The atmosphere is
getting more turbulent.
It's overloading
the systems.
I'm having difficulty
keeping the shields up.
Geordi...
we're safe now.
Good-bye.
( alarm blaring )
I'm losing power!
Total shield failure
in eight seconds.
Can we switch the inputs?
Almost.
Shields are failing!
Switching inputs.
( groans )
Is it working?
His vital signs
are stabilizing.
He's going to make it.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
We have succeeded in
disengaging Mr. La Forge
from the interface
and are en route
to Starbase 495.
You disobeyed
my direct order.
You put yourself
in grave danger.
I am not happy.
Yes, sir.
I take complete responsibility.
Data was only...
I will deal with Mr. Data
at another time.
Meanwhile, I will have
to write this incident
into your permanent record.
Yes, sir.
Dismissed.
Geordi?
I'm very sorry that
you didn't find your mother.
Thank you, sir.
You know, it's funny.
When I was down there,
it was so real.
I felt like I had a chance
to say good-bye.
( door closes )