( conversation and laughter )
So, tell me.
Why is it so important
that you find this man?
We had business dealings.
He owes me money.
Ooh.
Well, if we had
business dealings
I can tell you
that I wouldn't disappear.
Maybe we can discuss
that possibility.
Ooh.
But first...
I have to find him,
collect the money I'm owed.
I'll be closing in a few hours.
Perhaps we could, uh...
discuss this more privately.
If I don't find him,
I'm going to have to move on.
Oh...
Are you sure
you haven't seen him?
Human.
About... two meters tall...
smooth-headed.
Hmm.
No. I don't remember
anyone like that.
You're lying.
And you're a Betazoid.
I thought so.
Listen.
People that come in here...
they count on a certain amount
of anonymity.
And if I were to start
answering questions about them--
even to a very
beautiful woman--
well, I wouldn't be
in business very long.
And being a businesswoman,
I'm sure you understand.
( chuckling )
( sighs )
Great story.
I'll remember it
next time I'm in a knife fight.
Any luck?
I think the one over there
knows something.
He would not admit
to having seen the captain,
but he said anyone
who visited the ruins of Nafir
would probably
come here eventually.
I suspect he knows more.
Let's go.
Commander, I told...
My friend tells me
you know something
about the man
we're looking for.
The only reason
I'm talking to you
is that I have
a sister, too.
I explained to him
that we are looking for a man
who impregnated
your sister.
So, you can imagine how
much this means to me.
Family honor
is important.
If someone had defiled my sister
I would do anything,
pay anything
to find the one responsible.
And how much might
"anything" be?
As much as five bars
of gold-pressed latinum.
I think you've had
a little too much to drink.
You'd better leave.
On your way, Yranac.
I'm sorry...
but I think
he wants to stay.
Sit down.
RIKER:
That's my sister.
She's angry.
She's got a
vicious temper.
I wouldn't cross her.
You say one word
and you're a dead man.
Perhaps there's an element
of risk here
that I did not
fully appreciate.
Hmm. And how much more
latinum will it take
to offset this risk?
This isn't about latinum.
As a man with a sister--
a sister with a temper--
I can sympathize with you.
But...
how did you come here?
Do you have a ship in orbit?
Yes.
Then take me
with you.
You can drop me anywhere.
Agreed.
Now, talk.
The man you're looking for
was here several weeks ago.
There was a group of aliens
sitting at this table.
He was asking them questions.
Who were these "aliens"?
I don't know,
but they looked dangerous.
They attacked him.
He managed to incapacitate
three of them
before he was
knocked down.
He was thrown
against that wall
and fell there.
I'm picking up
Starfleet fiber traces
and human cellular debris.
Can you establish
a DNA reading?
There's something strange here.
The cell structures
are badly distorted.
It's as if they've been exposed
to some kind of
high-energy field.
A weapon discharge?
It could be.
I'm picking up some faint traces
of micro-crystalline damage
in the floor material.
But I'm not familiar with
the pattern I'm getting.
Who are you people?
You didn't say anything
about a weapon.
I hadn't finished yet.
You'll like this.
The man got
what was coming to him.
When they knocked him down
one of them took out
a weapon and fired.
He was vaporized.
He's telling the truth.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
RIKER:
Acting Captain's Log,
Stardate 47135.2.
Dr. Crusher has
positively identified
Captain Picard's DNA.
There is no doubt now
that he is dead.
( door chimes )
Come.
( sighing ):
How are you doing?
I'm all right.
The crew is
pretty shaken up.
I'm arranging
a memorial.
I think you should be the
one to deliver the eulogy.
I think you'd be better
at something like that.
Or Beverly.
She knew him the longest.
I know it's not
going to be easy,
but I think
it's important
that we face up
to what's happened.
You're in
command now.
The crew's looking
to you for guidance.
You don't understand.
I can't give the eulogy
because I won't be
at the service.
Will, a memorial service
helps to give everyone
a sense of completion.
It helps them begin
the healing process.
That's exactly the point.
I don't want to heal.
Will...
I have an open wound.
Right here.
It hurts like hell.
I don't want it to get better,
and I don't want to pretend
that everything's all right.
I know you're angry.
You're damn right!
And I intend to stay angry
until I find
whoever's responsible
for the captain's death.
Will, that's pretty
selfish of you.
Do you think you're
the only one in pain?
Do you think you have
the monopoly on loss?
Well, let me tell you something.
We're all hurting,
and we're all angry.
And whether you like it or not
you have a responsibility
to this crew!
And you can't just indulge
your personal desire
for revenge!
That is enough,
Counselor.
Deanna?
I'm sorry.
This is not about revenge.
This is about justice.
The captain died
in a bar fight for nothing.
Somebody has to answer
for that.
Then I can mourn.
( door opens, closes )
( console beeping )
Commander,
I am receiving a transmission
from Admiral Chekote
at Starbase 227.
I'll take it in
the Ready Room.
Aye, sir.
Sir.
I read your report, Commander.
My condolences to you
and to your crew.
Captain Picard's death is a loss
to the entire Federation.
Now, I see that you've asked
to postpone your mission
to the Argus sector.
For what reason?
I have a request, sir.
I would like to conduct
an investigation
into Captain Picard's death.
The Dessican authorities
have jurisdiction
in this case, Commander.
I know that, sir.
Frankly, I don't have
much confidence
in the authorities
on Dessica II.
There's every reason
to believe that they're corrupt.
Well, I suspect you're right,
but the question remains
are you the one to pursue this?
The captain's death
hit me pretty hard
and I may not be
completely objective,
but there's no one
who is more determined.
I won't rest until I find out
who's responsible.
All right, Commander.
I'm officially placing
the Enterprise on detached duty.
Your mission is
at your discretion.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
Mmm... mmm.
Ah! Commander Riker.
I've been meaning
to speak to you.
I was wondering
if you could move me
to better quarters.
I-I don't care much
for the decor here.
These are
the best quarters we have.
Hmm.
I was hoping now that you've
had a chance to relax
you might have remembered
some of the details
about the aliens you saw--
something you may have
forgotten before.
Sorry. My memory isn't
what it used to be.
They murdered
a man in cold blood
in full sight of everyone
in the bar
and you can't remember
anything about them?
Now that you mention it,
I do remember one thing.
They said they'd kill anyone
who talked about what happened.
Do you know where they went?
So, you know who they are
and you know
where I can find them.
Perhaps I do.
What do you want?
Not a great deal, Commander.
Just a shuttlecraft.
I believe I'd like
to travel for a while
see more of
the galaxy.
You understand.
A shuttlecraft.
Well, here's my offer.
Instead of the ship,
I'll give you some time.
Time?
If you're lucky,
you'll only spend
the next five years in prison,
instead of the next 20.
You've got 12
outstanding arrest warrants
for fraud and petty theft
in the Klingon Empire.
You tell me what you know,
I'll pull some strings.
Maybe they'll reduce
your sentence
after you've been extradited.
If I tell you what I know,
you must promise not
to give me to the Klingons.
I'll think about it.
Perhaps you could... send me
to a Federation
rehabilitation colony instead.
Talk.
The aliens were some kind
of mercenary group.
They've been operating
in this sector
for the last six months.
Where do we find them?
I heard one of them mention
the Barradas system.
I think they were headed there.
You think?!
That's all I know.
Riker to Data.
DATA:
Data here.
Take us out of orbit.
Set course
for the Barradas system.
Warp six.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
Barradas III is
the only Class-M planet
in this system
and it is listed
as unpopulated.
However,
sensors have detected
intermittent
energy signals
emanating
from its surface.
What's the source?
Well, the signals
are difficult
to localize,
but they could be emissions
from some kind
of power converter.
Which would indicate
a base or a ship.
What else do we know
about Barradas III?
The planet was used
as an outpost for the Debrune
approximately 2,000 years ago.
The Federation's
archaeological survey
has catalogued numerous ruins
on the surface.
Mr. Worf, I'd like
a security detail
to accompany the away team
to the surface.
I'll lead the away team.
Geordi, you're with me.
Mr. Data,
you have the bridge.
Aye, sir.
Commander?
As acting first officer
I must question your decision
to accompany the away team.
If Captain Picard
were here...
He's not.
I realize that, sir,
but if he were
and he wanted
to lead an away team
you would tell him
that the captain's place...
Is on the Bridge.
Not this time.
Ensign, you take
that area.
Yes, sir.
( birds chirping )
MAN:
Here you are, sir.
Geordi?
It's tough to get
accurate sensor readings.
There's an awful lot of
interference in the area.
From what?
I'm not sure.
It's very unlocalized,
but it could be atmospheric.
What do you make of these?
Well, these ruins
around here are
pretty ancient,
but I'd say that
this indentation
was made fairly recently.
It could be the site
of some battlefield.
This doesn't look
like any blast point
I've ever seen.
The shape is too perfect.
Commander, there's
micro-crystalline damage
all throughout
this area.
It's the same kind of pattern
that Dr. Crusher picked up
on the floor of that
bar on Dessica II.
WORF:
Commander!
I've found something.
( tricorder beeping )
it looks as if someone could
have just dropped it.
La Forge to Enterprise.
We are under attack
down here.
I repeat, we are under attack.
Commander, we've lost contact
with the away team.
Is there a malfunction?
No, sir.
The com system
is being jammed.
DATA:
What is the source?
Somewhere
on the surface.
Bridge to Transporter Room Two.
Can you get a lock
on the away team?
MAN:
Negative, sir.
There's too much interference.
I'm going to head
for those trees over there.
If I can get there, we might
be able to set up a cross fire.
Data to away team.
Please respond.
Data, we've
been attacked.
We've got one casualty
and commander Riker
has been taken captive.
Sir, the mercenaries
have beamed away.
They must have a base
or a ship nearby.
Can the sensors
locate anything?
Commander, we're picking up
a vessel leaving orbit.
Why was it not
detected earlier?
They could have been using
the planet as a shield.
( console beeping )
Sir, they're powering up
their weapon systems.
Raise shields.
Red alert.
( alarm wailing )
Damage report.
Minor hit on the port deflector.
No damage.
They're running, sir.
Their speed is warp 8.7
and holding.
I think they're
at their maximum.
Take us to warp nine
and pursue.
Lock phasers on target.
Sir, we should be
within phaser range
in 23 seconds.
Switching
to long-range scanners.
Commander, the sensor image
of that ship is extremely weak.
It's fading.
The ship doesn't register
on the long-range sensors.
I'm sorry, sir.
We've lost them.
Increase
the sensor field bandwidth.
Patch in
the lateral sensor arrays.
It's no good.
The signal's gone.
It just... disappeared.
Plot a course and take us back
to Barradas III.
Notify the away team
to prepare for transport.
Aye, sir.
Starfleet intelligence confirms
that a ship matching
this configuration
has been linked to raids
on several other planets
in this sector.
For the short time
it was within our visual range
we were able to take
sensor readings
of the mercenary vessel.
It appears to be encased in
an energy-absorbing material.
Although we can see the ship
this energy sheath renders it
virtually undetectable
to our long-range sensors.
There must be some way
we can track it.
LA FORGE:
Data?
I know this is a long shot,
but if I remodulate
the long-range sensor array
I might be able to make it
sensitive enough
to detect the ship.
Without a full
compositional analysis
of the energy sheath,
our chances of finding
the correct remodulation
sequence are remote.
Sir, they have taken
Commander Riker.
We must do something.
We cannot just sit here.
On the contrary,
Lieutenant,
that is precisely
what we must do.
Since there are
no viable alternatives
we will return to the surface
and attempt to determine
what these mercenaries
are doing on this planet.
An investigation
might reveal
some indication
of their purpose.
Please notify me
when you have assembled
your search teams.
Dismissed.
MALE 1:
What's the problem?
MALE 2:
I warned you not to push
the engines so hard.
Two of the power shunts
are on the verge of collapse.
We'll be lucky if we
can maintain warp six.
How long will it
take to repair?
I can try to realign
the warp core.
It'll take at least 11 hours.
But I'll have to shut
the engines down completely.
We're not stopping.
We can't afford to be
sitting helpless in space.
I want warp eight
available in five hours,
and I don't want to
hear your excuses.
What were you doing
on Barradas III?
William T. Riker
Commander, SC 231-427.
Oh, really?
Well, I am Arctus Baran,
and I don't have a number.
Now, what were you doing
on Barradas III, Commander?
We were studying
the ruins.
It was a scientific
expedition.
Don't patronize me.
Those ruins have been
studied for centuries.
There's nothing new
to learn from them.
Then what were you
doing there?
( gasping and moaning )
Oh, don't bother,
Commander.
You can't remove it.
It's a neural servo
connected directly
to your nervous system.
It lets me
control precisely
how much pain you feel.
This setting is
usually sufficient.
However, if necessary,
it can go much higher.
( yells )
These devices
were the idea
of my predecessor.
It's a convenient way
of enforcing discipline.
What happened to him?
He failed to
enforce it with me.
This is a waste of time, Baran.
Get rid of him now.
You should be more patient,
Vekor.
It might be rewarding.
We will wait.
Let the memory
of his pain
argue with him
for a while.
It might change
his attitude.
Vekor is right.
We should get rid of him.
It's dangerous having someone
from Starfleet on board.
Dangerous?
It might be profitable.
A Starfleet commander
is a valuable
hostage.
Starfleet won't
negotiate with us,
but they'll pursue us
as long as we have him.
( groans )
This discussion
is over.
Get back to your post, Vekor.
PICARD:
They're right, Baran.
And you know it.
I say kill him.
Now.
PICARD:
If he has nothing
to give us,
we should kill him now
and be done with it.
Everybody seems to recognize
that fact, except you.
I don't need a consensus
to run this ship, Galen.
( engine powering down )
( beeping )
What's going on?
I'm bypassing
the aft plasma couplings.
The power loss should only last
for a few seconds.
You should learn
not to limit your options.
Riker could be very useful to us
in the future.
He may not be as useful
as you think
if this is the same Riker
that I've heard about.
What Riker
might that be?
Commander
of the Enterprise
formerly assigned
to the USS Hood.
That's right.
Then you must be
the William T. Riker
with a history of
insubordination.
He was even once
relieved of duty
during the
Cardassian incident
at Minos Korva.
How do you know all this?
Look, I've been
smuggling artifacts
from Federation
sites for years.
You can't help
developing
a familiarity with certain
Starfleet personnel.
If we hadn't have
captured him,
he'd probably have
ended up before
a court-martial.
I've gotten out
of them before.
Look, he's no use to us.
Finish him now
or let me do it for you.
( alarm blaring )
Watch him.
We're accelerating.
What have you done?
It has nothing to
do with my repairs.
I think there's
a malfunction
in the engine's
intermix chamber.
Plasma pressure is rising.
Where's the malfunction?
It could be one of
any 30 subsystems.
It'll take time to locate.
I don't think you're
going to have the chance.
Plasma pressure has reached
critical levels.
Seal off
the intermix chamber.
I can't-- the override sequence
won't engage.
The antimatter-flow regulator
is locked open.
VEKOR:
Logic subsystem
still not responding.
Get out of the way.
ROMULAN:
Plasma pressure
has exceeded
maximum levels.
Eight percent above critical
and rising.
We have to jettison the core.
No.
We'll be stranded here.
The flow regulator is frozen.
Let me do it.
I've had a lot
of experience
with this sort
of systems failure.
I might be able
to do something.
Plasma pressure
is 11% above critical.
The containment fields
are beginning to degrade.
Go!
MERCENARY:
Flow regulator
is not responding
to manual override.
Containment fields
won't hold much longer.
Looks like you've got
a control logic lockout
on your regulator's
subsystem.
I'm going to attempt
to run an active bypass
through the plasma-flow
converter.
You! Start running
phase-locked feedback
through that regulator.
I want about
a six-second delay.
What are you saying?
I don't take orders from you.
You do as he says.
Plasma pressure is 14%
above critical.
If you fail...
We'll all be dead, anyway.
I just need
a few more seconds.
Plasma pressure is dropping.
We're back into safe levels.
You want to make sure
that doesn't happen again
you'd better reinitiate your
regulator subcompressors.
A full diagnostic of
your intermix chamber
wouldn't hurt, either.
Do it.
Put him in quarters
for now.
You still wish
you'd killed me?
( birds chirping )
The search teams
have reported in.
They found several
archaeological sites.
Each one has
been looted.
LA FORGE:
It's possible that
the micro-crystalline
damage I found
in these indentations is
the result of some kind
of high-energy
transporter beam.
But I still don't
understand.
There's nothing here that's
particularly valuable.
Why would anyone want to
steal any of these things?
Perhaps these artifacts
have a special value
to the Romulans.
The Romulans?
These structures were built
by the Debrune.
That race is an ancient
offshoot of the Romulans.
The ruins on the planet
where Captain Picard was killed
were also Romulan in origin.
The leader of the group
that attacked us was Romulan.
Perhaps they are controlling
the mercenaries.
The question remains--
why are they stealing
these artifacts?
There are several archaeological
sites in this sector
containing ruins
which are Romulan in origin.
These are the locations
that were attacked
by the mercenary vessel.
Looks like they did
a pretty thorough job.
The only sites not attacked
were on Calder II
Yadalla Prime
and Draken IV.
Yadalla and Draken are at
the far edge of the sector
but Calder II--
that's less than
a day from here
at maximum warp.
That would be
their next likely target.
According to this
there's a Federation outpost
at Calder II.
But it is only
a small science station.
It has limited
defensive capabilities.
I do not believe
it could withstand an attack
from the mercenary ship.
Mr. Worf, send a message
to the Federation outpost
on Calder II.
Advise them that if a ship
matching the configuration
of the mercenary vessel
approaches
they should attempt
to delay it until our arrival.
Ensign,
take us out of orbit.
Set a course
for the Calder System.
Warp nine.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
( door opening )
We don't have much time.
It's good to see you, Will.
I didn't expect
to meet you here.
I was looking
for the people
who killed you
on the surface.
A witness said
they saw you vaporized.
These mercenaries
use weapons
that can activate
their transporter.
It gives them
the opportunity
to beam things
away quickly
just by firing at them.
That's what
they did to me.
I don't understand
any of this.
Who are these people?
What are you doing
involved with them?
The site that I wanted
to study had been raided.
One of the artifacts
had been stolen.
The site had been
practically destroyed.
Well, I wanted
to find out who
was responsible.
I tracked them to that
bar on Dessica II.
Well, I must have asked
too many questions.
They captured me.
They wanted to find out
how much I knew about
their operation.
And then you became
part of their crew?
I convinced them
I was a smuggler
and that my name was Galen.
I offered to help them
appraise the artifacts
that they'd stolen.
Will, these are not
common thieves.
They are stealing
Romulan artifacts
from archaeological sites
throughout this sector.
Baran has me analyzing
each one of them
for a particular
particle signature.
Will, they are looking
for a specific artifact.
Why?
That's what
we have to find out.
Baran is the key.
I think that he knows
more about
what we're really looking for
than anyone else on this ship.
I want you to get close to him.
Try and get
his confidence.
That's why you set up
the engine failure--
because you knew that
I'd be able to fix it.
He also believes that you're
a less-than-perfect
Starfleet officer.
Will, I want you to
play into that role.
Baran and I...
Well, he doesn't care
very much for me.
But he has to tolerate me
because he needs my help
with these artifacts.
But if you and I
become enemies,
then there's a better chance
of you and he becoming friends.
All right.
I'll do what I can.
( door opening )
( groans )
What are you doing here?
Getting some answers.
Because you can't
get him to talk.
( groans )
No one conducts
an interrogation on this ship
without my permission.
Is that understood?
( groans )
Our next objective should prove
an interesting challenge.
We're headed for
the Sakethan burial mounds
on Calder II.
PICARD:
What?
Calder II isn't just another
archaeological site, you know.
It's a Federation outpost.
I don't see that
as a problem.
PICARD:
It's defended
by Starfleet.
You don't think they're
just going to stand by
while we walk in there
and take whatever we want?
I am familiar
with the tactical situation.
What are their defenses?
Nothing to worry about.
They have
a type-4 deflector shield
protecting the outpost
and the ruins.
They also have a minimum
of two phaser banks
and possibly photon torpedoes.
Is that enough
to worry about?
How do you know
so much about
this outpost?
Because I tried to smuggle
a Sakethan glyph stone
out of there
nearly two years ago.
I barely got away in one piece.
Our weapons are more
than a match
for their defenses.
I anticipate that
we'll be able
to destroy
the outpost
within 15 minutes.
Then we'll send in Tallera
and the landing party
to secure the relics.
Why don't we use Riker?
A Starfleet commander
could talk us past
the outpost security
without raising
their suspicions.
Then, when their shields go down
we could beam
the artifacts up here
without ever leaving
the ship.
Why would Riker help us?
Just because he's out of favor
with Starfleet
doesn't mean that he's ready
to betray them.
If he doesn't help us
we'll have
to destroy the outpost
and kill everyone on it.
He's still a Starfleet officer.
He won't want to take
innocent lives
if he can possibly
prevent it.
The last time we
engaged Starfleet
we lost a man.
We can't afford
any more casualties.
If we can avoid a battle,
I think we should.
All right, we'll try it.
We'll be at Calder II
within five hours.
You all know your duties.
I want this ship
prepared for battle...
in case your plan doesn't work.
Computer, reset diagnostic
for a new sample.
Lot number... 478-B.
Access spectral analysis
and begin scan, mode three.
COMPUTER:
Scan complete.
Terikon particle decay profile
does not fall within
specified reference range.
Probability of match: 0.04%
Computer, reset diagnostic
for a new sample.
Lot number 369-B.
Access spectral analysis,
mode two, begin scan.
Baran wants to see
the analysis of
the last lot.
He thinks you're moving
a little slowly.
You can tell Baran,
if he wants
the analysis done faster,
he can do it himself.
If he wants it done correctly,
he can wait.
Do you enjoy living
dangerously, Galen?
Baran can kill
you in an instant
if he activates
his control device.
I doubt that
he'll do that.
I've increased the accuracy
of the identification process
by a factor of ten.
I'm the best person
to analyze these artifacts.
Baran knows that.
He may need you now,
but I know Baran.
And I can tell you
he's not going to
back down forever.
You accomplish nothing
by provoking him.
I don't like operating
in the dark.
If I knew what the point
of this mission were,
why I was analyzing
these relics...
If Baran felt it were wise
to let the crew know that
I'm sure he would have.
Do you know
what all this is about?
What Baran knows, I know.
Then what's going on here?
Why are we risking our lives
taking these artifacts?
Who wants them?
I see no reason
to tell you anything.
But you can
rest assured.
I don't necessarily
share everything I know
with Baran either.
This conversation,
for example
will stay between us.
You can tell Baran every
word that I've said.
He knows that I
don't think much
of him as a leader.
He's been in charge
of this crew
for a long time.
Baran wouldn't last
five minutes as captain
if he didn't have
that control device.
The crew follow him
because they have no choice.
Baran's power is based
on fear and intimidation.
That almost sounds
like a prelude to mutiny.
If someone
were to challenge him,
the rest of the crew
would follow.
I was right.
You do like
living dangerously.
I like you, Galen.
I can tolerate a lot
from someone like you
but only to a point.
I intend to complete
this mission successfully
and get what's
been promised me.
If it looks as though
you're getting
in the way of that
I'll deal with you myself.
Commander, no one is allowed
on the surface
without prior authorization
from the Federation
Science Council.
I'm aware of
that, Lieutenant,
but your outpost is
in imminent danger of attack.
I would like to station
security personnel
on the surface
for your protection.
Now, I'm ordering you
to drop your shields.
I'm sorry, sir,
but the regulations
are very specific.
I can't do it.
If you'd like,
you can remain in orbit
until we contact
the Science Council.
But we're experiencing
some communication difficulties
right now, so that...
This isn't working.
They're delaying
on purpose.
Someone has warned them.
Charge main
disrupter array.
Destroy the outpost.
No! There's no time for that!
Starfleet will be here
any minute.
What are you doing?
I'm configuring the
disrupters to fire
a phase-resonant pulse.
If I can hit their
shield generator
with precisely
the right frequency
I should be able to take
it out with one shot.
Firing.
Their shields are down.
The artifacts should be located
in several small structures
arranged
in staggered formations.
I'm scanning.
I think I've found them.
Lock coordinates
and start bringing them up.
There should be at least
two more down there.
I've lost transporter lock.
They managed to get
their shields back up.
I need those artifacts.
Lock all disrupters
on target.
This time, I want
that outpost destroyed.
Direct hit
on their aft deflectors.
They are undamaged.
Ensign, scan
for Starfleet combat signals.
Is Commander Riker
aboard that ship?
I can't tell, sir.
Sensors are unable
to penetrate their hull.
Open a channel.
WORF:
Open.
This is the federation
starship Enterprise.
You are ordered to stand down.
Drop your shields,
and prepare to be boarded.
You sent them a message.
You told them
where to find us.
That's ridiculous.
When did I have a chance?
This is set to kill.
Order your ship
to disengage.
Activate visual.
Commander...
are you all right?
Tell them.
Mr. Data,
withdraw the Enterprise.
That's an order.
That is impossible, sir.
The ship you are on
has violated
a Federation outpost.
It is my duty to stop it.
I'm your commanding officer.
I'm giving you a direct order.
Understood?
Commander,
if you could explain...
I've never explained
my orders before.
I'm not about
to start now.
I'm not about to let him
blow this ship into space.
If I can set up
a low-level com link
between the two ships
I can use my personal
command codes.
I can deactivate
the shields.
Do it.
( console beeping )
Sir, we are receiving
some kind of signal
from the mercenary ship.
These are Commander Riker's
access codes.
He is attempting
to shut down
our shields.
That doesn't make sense.
He knows those codes
would have been changed
as soon as he was captured.
That is correct, Counselor.
He does know.
Mr. Worf...
prepare to drop shields.
Sir, we would be
totally defenseless.
I am aware of that.
Sir, as soon as they see us...
Mr. Worf,
that is an order.
Aye, sir.
It worked.
The shields
are dropping.
Fire.