Last time on Star Trek:
The Next Generation...
My friend tells me
you might know
about that man
we're looking for.
There was a group of aliens
sitting at this table.
He was asking them questions.
One of them took out
a weapon and fired.
He was vaporized.
This is about justice.
The captain died in a
bar fight for nothing.
( yells )
Those ruins have been
studied for centuries.
There's nothing new
to learn from them.
Then what were you
doing there?
( gasping and moaning )
Baran wouldn't last
five minutes as captain
if he didn't have that
control device.
That almost sounds
like a prelude to mutiny.
They captured me.
They wanted to find out
how much I knew
about their operation.
And then you became
part of their crew?
I convinced them
I was a smuggler.
Will, these are not
common thieves.
They are stealing
Romulan artifacts
from archaeological sites
throughout this sector.
Mr. Worf...
prepare to drop shields.
Sir... we would be
totally defenseless.
I am aware of that.
Fire!
And now, the conclusion.
Direct hit to
the port nacelle.
Only minimal damage.
Hit to the starboard nacelle.
Still, no appreciable damage.
Will must have done something
to their weapons.
I believe you
are right, Counselor.
It is now up to us
to play along.
Release inertial dampers and cut
power to decks 31 through 37.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
Set phasers to 25%.
Return fire.
Aye, sir.
Continue firing!
I've lost three plasma
relays on the disrupters.
Auxiliary power is...
is not available.
Transfer weapons control
to my station.
There's a way to bypass
the relays and feed power...
The antimatter containment
units are starting to buckle.
The Enterprise has
been badly damaged,
but they still have
superior firepower.
If we remain here,
we will be destroyed.
The logical course of
action is to withdraw.
( explosion )
We've done
enough damage.
Narik, set course.
180, mark 215.
Warp six.
Initiate.
They're preparing to activate
their warp drive, Commander.
Sir, we cannot track them
with our sensors
if they go to warp.
I can still disable them by--
I'm aware of the tactical
situation, Lieutenant.
Let them go.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I've gone over
every word,
every inflection,
every facial response,
and I still can't find
any kind of code
or hidden message.
I agree the existence
of such a message is remote,
but I believe we should check.
I'll keep trying.
Two starships have been sent
to intercept
the mercenaries
at Yadalla Prime and Draken IV,
in case they attempt
to attack those planets.
Inform Starfleet Command
that we will hold position
until further notice.
So... we are just
going to remain here?
Yes, but we will
continue to pursue
all avenues of
investigation.
If we had not let them escape,
this would not be necessary.
That is correct,
but I believe
Commander Riker wanted
us to let them escape.
LA FORGE: Commander?
Think I found something.
I've been studying the
com link Commander Riker used
to transmit his
command codes.
I didn't see anything at first,
but then I ran the transmission
through a subharmonic
analysis, and I found this.
It was sent by the same carrier
wave as the command codes.
It might be the message
we've been looking for.
Possibly.
I will attempt to
resequence the signal.
Begin running a search
for a decryption key.
I'm taking the
engines off-line.
How long will it take to
repair our battle damage?
It will take at
least five hours
to replace the anti-matter
containment unit.
You have three hours, Narik.
One minute beyond that,
and you'll answer
for it with your life.
I suppose
I should thank you.
None of us would be alive
if it weren't for you.
You're welcome.
What's wrong, Commander?
You having second thoughts
about betraying your comrades?
Because that's
what you've done--
betrayed them.
Betrayed them in order
to save yourself.
You used to be just
a second-rate officer.
Now, you're a traitor
and a coward.
How does that feel?
( groans )
I don't know.
How did that feel?
Enough!
Galen, go down to
the cargo hold.
Check out
those artifacts.
Move!
You can tell Baran that I'm
working as fast as I can.
What?
I'm trying to decide
if you're incredibly stupid
or incredibly smart.
Why didn't you
continue to fire
on the Enterprise when
their shields dropped?
You were there.
The disrupters lost power.
Computer, reset for
diagnostic of new sample.
Begin scan.
I've watched you handle
the weapon systems before.
You know exactly how to
bypass a problem like that.
And why do you continue
to argue with Riker?
It should be obvious
that by alienating Riker
you also alienate Baran.
And yet, you continue
to do so. Why?
COMPUTER:
Scan complete.
Terikon profile negative.
Computer,
reset diagnostic
for new sample and
begin scan.
Look, this isn't a
Romulan labor camp.
I don't have to
answer your questions.
And I don't give a damn
what you think.
COMPUTER:
Scan complete.
Terikon profile
positive.
98% probability of match.
Well...
whatever it is
we're looking for,
it seems that
we've found it.
Tallera to Captain.
BARAN:
Yes, what is it?
I'm in the cargo hold.
Galen's made a positive terikon
match on one of the artifacts.
Good. Bring it
to me immediately.
Don't let anyone
get near it.
TALLERA: Understood.
Tallera out.
That sounds
like good news.
Very.
It means we've
completed half
of what promises to be a
very profitable mission.
And even better than that,
I'm almost ready
to get rid of
your friend, Galen.
Really?
There's one more
artifact to find.
Once Galen confirms
that it's genuine,
his usefulness
on this ship
will come to a
very sudden end.
I can't say I'm sorry
to hear that.
Galen might be a
loudmouthed fool,
but sometimes,
he's quite perceptive.
His observations
about you, for instance.
Oh?
After what you
did on Calder II,
I doubt if you have
much of a future
in Starfleet.
Hmm...
Yes... I must say
I've come to the
same conclusion.
( chuckles )
Hmm.
Well, assuming that you
were not my prisoner,
what would you do now?
I guess I'd start looking
for a new career.
Ah.
There must be a
place where someone
with 15 years of Starfleet
technical knowledge
would be useful.
You wouldn't happen to
know a place like that?
Well... well, possibly.
However, there's one thing that
I've learned on this ship,
and that's to be cautious...
and never to
blindly embrace
what might appear to be
good fortune.
And right now,
you're a rather large
stroke of good luck.
I haven't exactly sworn
my undying allegiance
to you, either, Baran.
For instance,
I'd like to know
a little bit more
about this job.
Such as?
Such as, what you meant by
"very profitable mission."
Well, it's enough to know
right now that your share
would insure you a very
wealthy and long life
far from
the Federation.
Sounds promising.
It is.
Only you're gonna
have to earn it.
And you can start
by putting aside
your dislike for Galen
and becoming his friend.
Why?
Galen has allies
on this ship.
That could cause trouble...
if I decide to kill him.
I want you to find out
from him who they are.
Okay.
One more thing, Riker.
When the time comes...
I want you to kill Galen.
I have completed
my analysis
of the signal from
the mercenary ship.
I believe these groupings
represent bearings
and coordinates taken from
their navigational system.
So, you think this is
their flight plan?
Yes. If I am correct,
the mercenary ship
is headed toward
these coordinates
in the Hyralan sector.
Well, their maximum
speed is warp 8.7.
It would take them
at least 14 hours
to reach that position.
We could be
there in five.
Make it so.
Finally.
WORF: Set a course
for the Hyralan sector
and engage at warp nine.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant?
May I see you in
the ready room?
Of course.
Lieutenant, I
am dissatisfied
with your performance
as first officer.
May I ask in what way?
You continually question my
orders in front of the crew.
I do not believe this is
appropriate behavior.
With all due respect, sir,
I have always felt free
to voice my opinions,
even when they
differ from those
of Captain Picard
or Commander Riker.
That is true, but in those
situations, you were acting
as head of security,
not as first officer.
The primary role of the
second in command
is to carry out the
decisions of the captain.
In this case, me.
But is it not my duty to
offer you alternatives?
Yes. But once I have
made a decision,
it is your job
to carry it out
regardless of how you
may personally feel.
Any further objections
should be given to me
in private, not in
front of the crew.
I do not recall
Commander Riker
ever publicly
showing irritation
with his captain, as
you did a moment ago.
No, sir.
If you do not feel capable
of carrying out this role,
I will assign it
to Commander La Forge
and return you to tactical.
I would not enter it into
your record as a reprimand--
simply as a transfer.
I would prefer to remain
at my current post.
Then I expect you to conform
to the guidelines
I have laid out.
Aye, sir.
Dismissed.
Mr. Worf.
I am sorry if I have
ended our friendship.
Sir.
It is I who has jeopardized
our friendship, not you.
If you will overlook
this incident,
I would like to continue
to consider you my friend.
I would like that,
as well.
Thank you, sir.
Good to see you, too.
I've had some
unpleasant surprises.
Will, this isn't
a good idea.
Baran might
grow suspicious.
As a matter of fact, it was
Baran who sent me here.
He told me to pretend
to be friendly with you,
help you organize a mutiny,
so that he can determine who
your supporters are in the crew
and then
eliminate them.
Oh, what a tangled
web we weave.
I have difficulty remembering
whose side I'm on.
So, what have you been
able to find out?
When we reach the
Hyralan sector
we're supposed to rendezvous
with a Klingon transport ship.
I'm not sure, but I think
they may be delivering
another of the Romulan
artifacts to us.
A second artifact?
Oh, by the way,
that first artifact
is not Romulan--
it's Vulcan.
Vulcan?
Mm-hmm.
I have been looking over
the glyphs and pictograms
from the Calder II
artifact.
And although I don't
have enough data
to translate all
the inscriptions,
the alphabet and the symbology
is much more consistent
with early Vulcan
than Romulan.
Do these artifacts
have some religious
or cultural significance?
Something that would make them
valuable enough to kill for?
I don't know.
If I could just get access
to the Enterprise computer,
just for a few moments.
( sighs )
So, what will Baran do
once he's obtained
the second artifact?
You're supposed to
verify its authenticity.
Then I'm supposed to kill you.
Then I take your place.
Will, you always seem
to be after my job.
Well, as soon
as Baran feels
that I've outlived
my usefulness,
he can kill me simply
by using the neural servo.
So, I think we had better
start planning a mutiny.
We need a new captain,
and I've come to one
inescapable conclusion.
I agree, but I don't
think that's you.
Oh?
I don't trust you, Galen,
and I don't think
the rest of the
crew does either.
They're not gonna
follow you.
And who will
they follow-- you?
No. But they will
follow Tallera.
And so will I.
Who are you?
What?
You're no smuggler,
and I don't think
your name's Galen.
You will tell me who
you really are
and what you are
doing on this ship,
or I will kill you
right here.
What are you
talking about?
I will not play
games with you.
I found the message you
sent to the Enterprise.
When Riker was using
his command codes
to drop their shields,
you sent them a transmission
on the same
carrier wave.
You're a Starfleet
officer.
Do not deny it.
It is the only
logical conclusion.
My name is
actually T'Paal,
and I am a member
of the V'Shar.
Vulcan security?
That is correct.
I infiltrated
this ship a year ago
posing as a Romulan
mercenary.
I'm here to investigate a
possible threat to Vulcan.
What sort
of threat?
First things first, Galen.
Who are you?
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
Very well.
To answer your question,
for several years now
there has been a
small, but growing movement
of extreme isolationists
on Vulcan--
a group that believes
contact with alien races
has polluted our culture
and is destroying
Vulcan purity.
This group advocates
the total isolation of Vulcan
from the rest of the galaxy
and the eradication
of all alien influences
from our planet.
That sounds like...
an illogical philosophy.
Agreed.
But extremists often have
a logic all their own.
Tell me, Tallera.
What are these artifacts
that we've been collecting?
I know that they are
Vulcan in origin.
I'm sure you are
familiar with
the ancient history
of my people--
before we found logic,
before we found peace.
You were much
as my people once were--
savage, warlike.
There was even a time
when we used our telepathic
abilities as a weapon--
a time when we learned
to kill with a thought.
The Stone of Gol?
You know of it?
I know the story
from Vulcan mythology.
The Stone of Gol is real,
but there is nothing
supernatural
or magical about it.
It is a psionic
resonator--
a device which focuses and
amplifies telepathic energy.
It is one of the most
devastating weapons
ever conceived.
But according to the legend, the
stone was destroyed
by the gods when the Vulcan
people found their way to peace.
The resonator was believed
to have been destroyed
during the Time
of the Awakening.
Only one piece is known
to have survived,
and it was placed in a
Vulcan museum under heavy guard.
A year ago, that piece was
stolen from the museum.
Soon after,
mercenary ships began
raiding archaeological sites
across the quadrant.
We believe a member
of the Isolationist Movement
is attempting to
reassemble the resonator.
A telepathic weapon.
My orders are to find
that assassin and stop him.
It would seem that Baran has
to deliver these artifacts
to the assassin
in order to get paid.
Therefore...
you and I should continue
our masquerade.
Agreed.
But, Captain, I cannot allow
the resonator to be assembled.
If necessary, I will destroy
this ship, its crew--
all of us-- to prevent
that from happening.
DATA: Acting Captain's Log,
Stardate 47160.1.
The Enterprise is entering
the Hyralan sector,
which I believe to be
the next destination
of the mercenary ship.
I'm picking up
a small vessel
bearing 127, mark 335.
Is it the mercenary ship?
No, sir,
it's a Klingon ship.
A Toron-class shuttlecraft--
one person.
Open a channel.
This is Lieutenant
Commander Data
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
Koral.
I take it that is your name?
May I inquire
as to your destination?
No.
DATA: May I ask the
purpose of your journey?
No.
Perhaps I have not made
our intentions clear.
We are
investigating...
He seems most...
uncooperative.
He may have been curt, but
he was also very worried
and even a
little scared.
Sir... may I recommend
that we bring the shuttlecraft
aboard with our tractor beam,
search it
and interrogate Koral?
According to the terms of
the Klingon Federation Treaty,
Koral has every right
to free transit
through Federation space.
We cannot board or search
his vessel without cause.
Yes, sir.
However, the treaty
does give us the right
to conduct health and safety
inspections on any ship
in our space.
Health and safety inspections?
I am not certain that
using this clause
as an excuse to
conduct a search
would be consistent
with the spirit
of the treaty.
Yes, sir.
However...
if Koral wishes to
contest our actions,
he can file a protest with the
Judge Advocate General's office.
Bring the shuttle aboard.
Then you and Dr. Crusher
may begin the inspection.
Aye, sir.
Hello.
I'm Dr. Crusher,
and this is Lieutenant Worf.
We're here to
conduct a health
and safety inspection
of your ship.
"Health and safety
inspection."
That's right.
Uh, you know, um...
radiation leaks,
um... biochemical
contamination, um...
other health hazards.
( whispering )
Excuse me.
Well, no radiation so far.
I'm sure you're glad
to hear that.
Right.
( console beeping )
There's an
incoming message.
It's from the Klingon shuttle.
It was sent approximately
15 minutes ago.
He's at the rendezvous
coordinates
but he's been detained
by the Enterprise.
And that's all there is.
He's stopped transmitting.
The Enterprise?
Now, how could
they have found out
about the rendezvous,
Commander?
BARAN:
Quiet!
All that matters now
is that the Enterprise
has the second artifact
in their possession.
We don't have
a choice.
We'll have to board
the Enterprise
and take the artifact.
Do you have any idea
how many security officers
there are on board
a ship like that?
No, I don't.
But he does.
I could get us
on the Enterprise.
I can find the artifact.
Oh, yeah.
Very convenient!
We beam you back aboard
your old ship.
We have to take a risk that
you won't change your mind
and betray us.
I have saved your life
twice already, Galen.
I would think you
would begin to show
some gratitude by now.
Galen, if you're so worried
about Riker,
then you can go on the
raiding party and watch him.
Agreed.
Draw weapons and equipment
for a raiding party of five.
If you're thinking
of betraying us
to your friends
on the Enterprise,
you might remember that
I still have the ability
to kill you at the first
sign of trouble.
I haven't forgotten.
I have an additional
task for you--
one that will
prove your loyalty.
This raid is an opportunity
to get rid of Galen.
Once you've found
that artifact...
kill him.
I'm sure the health
and safety inspection
won't last much longer.
And in the meantime,
I'm really glad
that we have this opportunity
to get to know you.
May I ask what
business you're in?
Lieutenant Worf has programmed
our replicators
to make a very good
approximation
of Klingon bloodwine.
I believe you will find it
to your liking.
( wine spilling )
Well, that's my third scan
and I still haven't found
anything out of the ordinary.
He must be hiding
something.
We should download his computer
memory and analyze it.
I'd have a hard
time defending that
as part of a safety
inspection.
We could claim
that the computer
was generating abnormal
radiation signatures.
Worf, we're on pretty
shaky ground as it is.
We can't just...
( groans )
Don't!
Watch that door.
What is going on?
Shut your mouth,
Klingon!
I guess you're surprised
to see me, Doctor.
You could say that.
I've had a change
of profession.
It's not in here.
Hey, you.
Where's the artifact?
I do not know what
you're talking about.
Use your brain.
They wouldn't be searching
the shuttlecraft if
they had the artifact.
Koral must have it.
Where is that Klingon pilot?
In the observation lounge
with Data and Troi.
How far?
12 decks away.
Security will not allow
you to get that far.
They won't get
the chance.
We'll use the transporter
in that shuttle.
We'll beam directly
to the observation lounge.
Sorry about this.
Let's go!
If you could tell us...
something about the nature
of your mission...
( whoosh of active transport )
What is this?
NARIK: Quiet!
Does he have it?
( beeping )
This is it.
Are you sure, Galen?
Yes, I can recognize
the inscription pattern
from the first artifact.
Commander Riker...
by taking this action,
you risk charges of assault,
theft, piracy and treason.
Really?
Then I guess adding
one more charge wouldn't hurt.
( yells )
( gasps )
Is he dead?
Yes.
Good.
Activate the transporter.
Security alert.
Medical emergency team
to the observation lounge.
Data to Bridge.
Raise shields
and begin sensor sweeps
for the mercenary ship.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
He's all right.
He's only stunned.
I must admit...
I am experiencing a
similar sensation.
( groans )
This is gonna take a
little time to explain.
Set course 310,
mark 215.
Warp six.
Where is it?
I have something else
for you, Baran.
Tell him
what happened, Narik.
Riker turned on us.
He tried to kill Galen
before we beamed back.
PICARD: He might have killed
all of us, and I believe
he was acting under your
direct orders, Baran.
You betrayed us.
This has gone
far enough.
I think it is time that
we had a new Commander--
someone who would lead us
to those profits
that we've been promised.
Oh, really?
And who would that be, Galen?
You?
He's plotted
this all along.
Opposed me at
every turn.
Endangered all of us
by refusing to
follow his orders.
To follow your orders--
the orders of a small
man trying to fill
a role too big for him.
I say it's time for a change.
Who's with me?
Hmph.
It's over, Baran.
Not quite.
As long as I have this,
I'm still captain of this ship.
You can't kill all of us.
You need us to
run this ship
more than we need
you to command it.
I don't have to
kill you all.
Just you, Galen.
( choking )
What happened?
I switched the
transponder codes.
Given his feelings about me,
it seemed a sensible
thing to do.
Baran was nothing.
We have a mission
to complete,
and the crew
needs a leader.
There'll be no more punishment
on board this ship.
Now, do your duties,
and I'll see to it
that we complete our mission
and get our payment.
Remove that.
Orders?
Maintain our present
course and speed for now.
I'm gonna find out
when and where
we're supposed to
deliver our cargo.
Aye, Captain.
Worf to Commander Riker.
Minister Satok
of Vulcan Security
is standing by on
a secure channel.
Put it through in here.
Greetings, Commander.
How may I be of service?
Minister, I thought
I should let you know
the mercenary ship that has
been raiding planets
in the Taugan system is probably
on its way to Vulcan right now.
I do not understand.
I'm sorry-- it's been a
difficult couple of days.
I know that one
of your operatives
has been on a mercenary ship
investigating
the possible reassembly
of a psionic resonator.
I didn't want someone
to make a mistake
and start firing at them
when they approach your planet.
Commander, I believe
there is a problem.
We have no operative
aboard a mercenary ship.
PICARD:
According to Baran's logs
we are to deliver
the two pieces
to the T'Karath
Sanctuary on Vulcan.
I know that place.
It was an underground
stronghold
for one of the factions
during the last civil war.
It's been abandoned
for centuries.
Galen to Bridge.
Alter course for Vulcan.
VEKOR:
Understood.
Oh, I wonder if
you can possibly
help me with something.
I have been able to translate
most of the writings
on these two pieces.
For the most part,
they're warnings of death
and destruction to anyone
who opposes the resonator.
But...
I am not able to
determine what appears
on the anterior side.
For example...
this symbol represents
the Vulcan God of War,
and this, the God of Death.
But... if you look
really carefully,
you can see a
third symbol is missing.
Now, that obviously should
belong to the final piece.
Now, what's
odd about this
is that the God of
Death and War
would typically always
stand alone on an artifact.
They'd never be combined
with a third glyph.
Fascinating...
but I am not an
archaeological expert.
I-I'm really anxious
to see the final artifact
because it might provide
a valuable insight
into Vulcan mythology.
When we arrive at Vulcan
I will take these pieces
to a secure holding area
before going on
to the sanctuary.
I prefer to go alone.
It will arouse
less suspicion
on the part of
the isolationists.
Well, there should
be no problem
about our entering orbit.
I asked Commander
Riker to contact
the Vulcan authorities
from the Enterprise--
let them know that
we were approaching.
Why did you do that?
Well, I... didn't want to
risk a misunderstanding.
Someone might have
mistaken this
for an actual raid.
It was a wise precaution.
Perhaps I should contact
the Enterprise...
have them meet
us at Vulcan,
just in case these
isolationists try to escape.
Your offer is appreciated,
but our security forces
are more than adequate.
I see. Um...
do you think it's wise for
you to go there alone?
After all, they were
expecting Baran to show up.
Now, don't you think if
I were to accompany you,
it might seem
more plausible--
Captain, I do
understand your human
emotional need to be there
at the final moment.
But this is a
Vulcan matter.
Of course.
Thank you.
We have entered
orbit of Vulcan.
Tallera, I've decided
on a change of plan.
Take one of the
artifacts with you.
Leave the other one here.
As soon as we have
our payment in full,
we'll complete the delivery.
That was not the agreement.
I realize that.
But it's safer for all concerned
to leave one behind.
They will not pay us
until they get both pieces.
They've been waiting
a long time for this.
They're not gonna
take any risks.
Now, take one of the
artifacts and beam down.
That is all I was waiting for.
Go to the navigational computer
and check file 137/Omega.
You'll find a message
secretly transmitted
to the Enterprise containing
our entire flight plan.
She's right.
The message was
sent by Galen.
He's a Starfleet officer.
Tallera is right...
but what she's not telling you
is that those artifacts
she's holding
are part of an
incredibly powerful weapon.
There's no reward waiting
for you down
on the surface.
As soon as she's got
those artifacts,
she'll leave you behind to
be captured by Starfleet.
I don't care what it is
you want, Tallera.
I don't care if that's a
weapon for your personal use,
or if you're really just making
a delivery as planned.
All I care about is my money.
So, I propose
a compromise.
Narik and I will go
with you to the surface
to guarantee that we
receive our payment.
After that, you can go
anywhere you want.
Agreed.
Bring him, as well.
We'll use him as a hostage
if Starfleet arrives.
If not, we'll kill him
on the surface.
There.
Your reward, as promised.
NARIK:
Is it all there?
No, this is less than half
of what we were promised.
Where's the rest of it?
That is all
I could manage.
I suggest you take it
and leave.
I did not come
this far to be cheated.
I want it all now!
Very well.
You will get what you deserve.
( screams )
( shrieks )
Go ahead, Captain.
Pick up the phaser.
See what good it will do.
You'll never get
away with this.
Starfleet will never stand by
and watch you tear apart
one of the founding
worlds of the Federation.
How little you understand what
you're facing, Captain.
You're used to fighting
enemies like yourself--
people on ships
with defense shields,
energy weapons,
warp drives.
But this is unlike
anything you've ever faced.
This is the power
of the mind.
Pick up the phaser, Captain.
PICARD:
Listen to me, all of you.
Drop your weapons!
Do it!
Don't make any
aggressive movements.
The resonator amplifies
violent feelings
and emotions.
And that's why you wanted me
to pick up the phaser.
That's how you were able
to kill Narik and Vekor.
But I can see the symbol
on that third artifact...
and it is the Vulcan
symbol for peace
standing between the
symbols for war and death.
It's a warning that the
power of the resonator
can be overcome
by peace.
You are about to see
how wrong you are.
Empty your minds
of violent thoughts!
No!
Think, Tallera.
2,000 years ago
your people were
being consumed by war.
But when peace
came to Vulcan,
the resonator
became useless.
That's why it was dismantled.
( grunts )
Oh...
You were right, Tallera.
The resonator
cannot be stopped
by phasers
and shields.
But it can be
defeated by peace.
( whimpers )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47169.2.
Security Minister Satok
has taken Tallera into custody
and begun a search for the rest
of the isolationists.
Once we realized that
you were no longer
on the mercenary ship,
we scanned the surface
for your neural implant.
We tracked the signal
into the caverns.
What will become of
the resonator, sir?
Satok has assured me
that all three pieces
will be destroyed.
It is unfortunate
it cannot be studied.
The resonator is
a key artifact
from a remarkable
period of history.
Oh, normally, I would be
the first one to agree.
But perhaps some things
are best left in the past.
What's going to happen to the
mercenaries?
Oh, they will be detained
by the Vulcan authorities
for the moment.
( yawning )
But they're also facing
charges from the Klingons,
the Cardassians,
the Ferengi, and at least
seven other worlds.
I don't think we'll be
hearing from them for a while.
Number One, will you set
a course for Starbase 227?
I'll join you on
the Bridge shortly.
Wait a minute.
You've been declared dead.
You can't give orders
around here.
DATA: If we are to
adhere to the exact letter
of Starfleet regulations,
then technically, sir,
you have been
declared a renegade.
In fact, I believe
you are facing
12 counts of
court-martial offenses.
You cannot give orders
either, sir.
That's quite right.
And as I am supposed to be dead,
I'll go and get some sleep.
And Mr. Data,
I suggest that you escort
Commander Riker to the brig.
Aye, sir.
( chuckles )
This way, sir.
Data, he was joking.
You know that, right?
Data?