Data,
there you are.
We need to install that
plasma conduit right away.
We're bringing the
new warp core on line
in less than
three hours.
I will go to deck 20
and begin modifications.
Great. I'll meet you
in Engineering
as soon as you're
finished there.
This ought to be a lot of fun!
( phone ringing in distance )
( ringing gets louder )
( men grunting )
Excuse me.
( ringing continues )
Do you have authorization
to work in this area?
You are dismantling
a warp plasma conduit.
I must ask you
to stop.
( high-pitched shrieking )
Be quiet!
( shrieking stops )
( electrical fritzing
and crackling )
( growling )
( growling continues )
( men grunting )
( electrical fritzing
and crackling )
( grunting continues )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47225.7.
Commander La Forge has
completed the installation
of our new warp core.
We are preparing
to test its capabilities.
Something wrong,
sir?
I just got a message
from Starfleet Command.
Bad news?
You could say that.
I've been invited
to the annual Starfleet
admirals' banquet.
My condolences.
I've managed to avoid it
for the past six years
but now it would seem
that my luck has run out.
Can't think
of anything
more tedious.
50 admirals shaking hands,
making dull conversation.
Uninteresting food,
boring speeches...
Can't you think
of some excuse
to get out of it?
After six years,
Number One,
I don't think I have
any excuses left.
Geordi, have you
ever had a nightmare?
Yeah,
sure, Data.
Everybody does
from time to time.
I have had 111 dreams
since I first discovered
this program
nine months ago.
In all of that time,
I have never experienced
such strange and
disturbing imagery.
I believe it
was a nightmare.
Well, nightmares are a part
of dreaming, Data.
Maybe you've
just discovered
another level
to your program.
Perhaps.
( beeping )
I have also noted
that I am spending
an inordinate
amount of time
thinking about
nightmare imagery.
One could almost say
I am preoccupied.
Well, it's perfectly
normal, Data.
Sometimes when
I have a nightmare
I can't shake that
weird feeling
for a couple
of days.
WOMAN:
Commander La Forge?
Speaking
of nightmares.
I just finished
recalibrating
the starboard
EPS module.
That's great,
Ensign, thank you.
It's just
like you said--
"Reset the power tap"--
and the module
came right on line.
You have such a wonderful grasp
of engineering principles.
I'm learning so much
just being
around you.
( clearing throat )
I'll tell you what--
Why don't you
help Farrell
check out the
deuterium cartridges.
We're just about to bring
the warp core on line,
all right?
Anything you say.
Geordi, you do not seem
to appreciate
Ensign Tyler's
enthusiasm.
She's enthusiastic,
all right--
about me.
I do not understand.
She's got a crush
on me, Data.
You do not share
her affection?
Exactly,
and quite frankly,
it's beginning to get
a little bit...
uncomfortable.
I believe
I understand.
You are concerned about
unintentionally hurting
Ensign Tyler's
feelings.
Yeah.
Something like that.
It would appear
that you require
a third party
to intervene
on your behalf.
I will be happy
to speak to her.
No, Data.
I'll take care
of it myself.
Thanks.
Geordi, when I first
awoke from my nightmare
there was a brief
moment when I...
PICARD:
Bridge to Commander La Forge.
What's our status?
We're ready to bring
the new core on line, Captain.
Stand by.
( beeping )
All right.
Let's do it.
Initializing...
deuterium infusion sequence.
It's a thing of beauty,
isn't it?
Now let's see how
fast she can run.
La Forge to Bridge.
Warp power
at your discretion, captain.
Acknowledged.
Ensign Gates, set course
for Starbase 219.
Warp six.
Engage.
Bridge
to Engineering.
Mr. La Forge, why
isn't my ship moving?
I'm on it, Captain.
There's a warp plasma
conduit out of alignment...
but I think I've
got it fixed now.
Ready, sir.
Very well.
Ensign Gates.
( engines powering down )
Mr. La Forge.
Stand by, Captain.
Captain, I am taking
the warp coil engines
off-line.
( sighs )
La Forge to Bridge.
I'm sorry, sir,
but we're going to
have to reconfigure
this plasma conduit.
It's going to take at least
a couple of hours, sir.
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Enter.
Hello, Data.
Counselor.
What are you doing?
I have been
watching Spot sleep.
In the past
15 minutes
he has had
12 muscle spasms
which indicates
he was dreaming.
I have often wondered
what Spot dreams about.
His twitching
and rapid breathing
would seem
to suggest anxiety
but Spot has
never seen a mouse
or any other form
of rodentia.
He has never
encountered an insect
or been chased
by a canine.
I understand you've had some
interesting dreams recently.
Geordi was worried
about you
and he wanted me to check in
and see how you were doing.
That was very
thoughtful of him.
I have been debating
whether or not
to initiate
another dream sequence.
Because of
the nightmares?
I have found them
to be quite...
unsettling.
Data, you shouldn't be afraid
of dark imagery in your dreams.
It's a natural expression
of your
unconscious--
if you have
an unconscious.
I'm not sure how your
positronic brain works
but if it's
anything like ours,
then there's a part of you
that's trying to express itself
through
your dream state.
And I think you
should allow yourself
to experience it.
As Sigmund Freud said--
"Dreams are the royal road
to the knowledge of the mind."
Hmm.
Thank you, Counselor.
I believe I will initiate
a dream program now.
Let me know
how it goes.
Good night, Data.
Good night,
Counselor.
Good night, Spot.
( meows )
( stilted yawn )
( smacks lips )
Computer, dim lights.
Mmm...
Delicious.
What kind of cake
are you eating?
It is a cellular peptide cake
with mint frosting.
Would you
like a bite?
No, thank you.
( phone ringing )
Excuse me, Mr. Worf.
Aren't you going
to answer that, Mr. Data?
Sir?
That damn ringing.
Answer it,
will you?
Yes, sir.
( men murmuring )
Please identify
yourselves.
I must ask what you
are trying to...
( high-pitched shrieking )
Be quiet!
( shrieking stops )
( ringing continues )
Please...
Don't hurt me, Data.
I am sorry, Counselor.
No...
Don't.
No! No!
Data!
TROI:
Data.
Data!
What is wrong?
We've been trying to wake you
for the last five minutes.
When you didn't show up on time
in Engineering, I got worried.
My internal chronometer
was supposed to wake me
35 minutes ago.
You must have
overslept.
That is not possible.
Something
is wrong.
I can't find
anything wrong
with your internal
time-base.
As far as I can tell,
your primary systems
check out fine.
I will compare
my autonomic logs
with the ship's
chronometer.
Perhaps we have
overlooked something.
You know...
Data,
there's an awful lot
we don't know
about your dream program.
Maybe it was designed
to cause side effects.
I mean, for all we know,
Dr. Soong might have intended
for you to oversleep
from time to time.
It's part of
the human experience.
It is a possibility.
However, I would prefer
to make certain
there are no anomalies
in my neural nets.
You know, I'm curious.
What were you dreaming about
when we woke you up?
I have not fully assimilated
its impact.
I would prefer to study
the images further
before discussing them.
Hmm... sounds like it must
have been pretty strange.
"Strange" is not
a sufficient adjective
to describe
the experience.
( in Austrian accent ):
Tell me more about this... cake.
It is difficult
to explain.
Counselor Troi's body
was a cake.
Her upper body.
Describe the knife you used
to cut the counselor.
It had a black handle
and a serrated blade
and it was quite long.
How long?
25 centimeters
in length.
Hmm. Hmm, hmm, hmm.
And what
happened next?
One of the workmen pointed
to her right shoulder.
At that moment,
I had an overwhelming urge
to cut a piece
out of the cake.
And did you?
Yes.
As I began
slicing the cake,
she reacted as though
I was causing her pain.
Yet I could not
stop cutting.
That is when I woke up.
Hmm.
Dr. Freud,
I am curious...
Eh, eh, eh, eh.
I am curious.
What do my nightmares
mean?
I believe you are experiencing
a classic dismemberment
dream.
Or, in your case,
being a mechanical man
a dismantlement dream.
I do not understand.
Your mechanistic qualities are
trying to reassert themselves
over your human tendencies.
Ego and id struggling
for domination.
The workmen symbolize
the ever-present id
constantly working
to destroy the ego.
Now, the image
of Counselor Troi--
a female--
is devoured by you,
clearly indicating
an unconscious desire
to possess
your own mother.
But I do not
have a mother.
Do not interrupt.
The knife--
in its violent connotation--
suggests a certain feeling
of sexual inadequacy.
But I have
no sexual desire.
Ach! Impotence on top
of everything!
It is all becoming clear
to me now.
There might be
a paper in this.
I do not believe I am
being helped by this session.
Classic transference!
Your anger toward me
is, in fact,
the animosity you feel
toward your father.
You are a polymorphously
perverse individual, Mr. Data
and I recommend
full psychoanalysis.
I believe I can
fit you in, uh...
next Tuesday.
That will not be necessary.
Computer,
end program.
( communications beep )
Captain, incoming message
from Admiral Nakamura.
On screen.
Admiral.
Captain.
We were expecting you
this morning.
Is there a problem?
Actually, we have
been experiencing
a few minor difficulties
with our new warp core,
but my chief engineer assures
me that we will be underway
within the hour.
You're not trying to avoid
this particular engagement,
are you, Picard?
No, no, certainly not.
I'm... really looking forward
to it.
Good.
I'll expect you soon.
Nakamura out.
I think he's
on to you, sir.
Hmm.
La Forge to Bridge.
Go ahead, Geordi.
We've just started
it up, Captain.
All systems
are holding steady.
Ready when you are, sir.
Ensign Gates.
Set a course...
and engage.
PICARD:
Engineering, report.
The warp field
has collapsed, sir.
It looks like
we've blown
the entire power
converter, Captain.
Impulse engines
are down, too.
We're not
going anywhere.
But I know just
how to fix this.
Give me two,
three hours, tops.
Talk about
going nowhere fast.
( sighs )
Mr. Worf, open a channel
to Starbase 219.
Advise
Admiral Nakamura
I'll be a little later
than I thought.
Aye, sir.
Tyler, how are
you coming
with that
relay diagnostic?
Almost done, sir.
Excuse me.
I need the plasma
inverter.
It appears Ensign Tyler
still has a crush on you.
It is clear you did
not speak to her.
No, Data, I haven't
had the time.
Listen, I want you
to take this brace coil
and run a metallurgical
scan on it for me.
See if there are
any microfractures.
Something wrong,
Data?
I am reminded
of a recent dream.
( chuckling )
This brace is
reminiscent of...
( phone ringing in distance )
( ringing continues )
RIKER:
Are you going to answer that,
Commander?
What are you waiting for?
Answer it!
Hello?
FREUD:
Kill them.
You must kill them all...
before it's too late.
Data...
Data,
what's wrong?
I do not know.
Everything seems to remind me
of the nightmare.
Objects, sounds, smells.
And now I have seen elements
of the dream in a waking state.
I cannot explain it.
Data, if you were one
of my human patients,
I might be concerned
right now.
I'd say you've had
a waking dream--
or an hallucination.
But you're
not human.
I think we might be
looking at some kind
of technological
problem.
I have run three
complete self-diagnostics.
All of my systems are
functioning normally.
Perhaps Dr. Freud
was correct.
The knife I dreamed about
is the embodiment
of my unconscious desire
to inflict
violence.
Data, even Freud said
"Sometimes a cigar
is just a cigar."
but the bottom
line is
I think you're developing
an almost obsessive interest
in your own
inner workings.
I'd almost call it
the beginnings
of a neurosis.
That is not possible.
Why not?
You've eliminated all the
technical explanations
and it makes sense
that as your neural net
becomes more complex,
more human,
that you might
experience
the same kind of psychological
complexities as a human.
Do really think
that is possible?
Data, you must be
the first person
who's come into my office
and been excited at
the prospect of a new neurosis.
But yes, I do think
it's possible
and I'd like to start
counseling you
on a regular basis.
Daily?
No, we'll start weekly,
and as a first step,
I'd like you to shut down
your dream program
until our next session,
just to be on the safe side.
Give yourself
a chance
to reflect on
this experience.
Thank you, Counselor.
I look forward
to our next meeting.
And Data...
Next time... see me
before you see Sigmund.
Admiral, I can explain...
NAKAMURA:
Let me guess.
Your new warp core is
malfunctioning again.
Unfortunately, the problem has
affected our impulse systems.
At the moment,
we... are adrift.
Are you expecting to have
this problem fixed soon?
Or shall we send out
a tow ship to bring you in?
That will not
be necessary.
I have every confidence
in my Engineering staff.
I will be
at the banquet on time.
Picard out.
Have you tried
reconfiguring the
plasma conduits?
Yes, Captain,
two hours ago.
What about the relays?
Are you absolutely
certain
that you don't need
a new phase inverter?
I am currently running
a level-three diagnostic
of the relays, sir.
We will have the results
of the analysis
in approximately
ten minutes.
( sighing )
I see.
Oh, perhaps I could
reconfigure
these isolinear chips.
No, sir--
please don't touch that.
Captain,
Commander Data and I
have the situation
under control.
Now, if you'd just let us
take care of it,
the work would go
much faster.
Captain, we could use
an extra hand
moving
the containment pods,
if it wouldn't be
an imposition.
Oh, no.
Not at all.
I'd be delighted.
Good work, Tyler.
I thought
he'd never leave.
Data, I want you
to give me a hand
locking down
this plasma con...
Data?
Data!
( gasps )
Deck 36.
( sighs )
Hello, Data.
Are you all right?
What are you
doing?
Hold very still,
Counselor.
No!
( screaming )
Ever since you
gave Alexander
that music program,
he's been playing it
all night... every night!
I just wanted to
broaden his horizons.
Besides,
he likes it.
It is screeching,
pounding dissonance.
It is not music.
Worf, it's better
than music.
It's jazz.
( door opens )
Medical emergency,
deck 17,
section three alpha.
We're on our way.
I believe I had another waking
dream, sir.
but this time,
I had an uncontrollable urge
to eliminate
the image I saw.
And what you saw was
some sort of mouth
on Troi's shoulder.
Yes, sir.
And for a reason I
cannot explain
I had the need
to destroy it.
What about me?
Did you see one of those mouths
on my head as well?
No, sir, I saw a straw
coming out of your head.
A straw?
As I said before,
these are all images I
originally experienced
in my dream program.
I do not have
a rational explanation for them.
Mr. La Forge?
Captain, we've run
every possible diagnostic
on Data's positronic net
we can think of.
We can't find
anything wrong.
I could run
a sub-polymer scan,
but it would take some time
to set up the equipment.
Make it so.
In the meantime, Mr. Data,
I'll have to relieve you of duty
and confine you
to your quarters.
A sensible precaution,
sir.
Data...
( panting )
Deanna, you're
in Sick Bay.
It's all right.
Data...
He's not here.
Just try to relax.
This vascular pad
has healed the wound,
but you've lost
a lot of blood,
so I would like you
to lie still for a while.
That's odd.
There shouldn't be
any discoloration
after the treatment.
This looks like
some sort of rash.
What is it?
( beeping )
I'm picking up
cellular degradation
but it doesn't appear
to be related
to the lacerations.
There's also
some kind
of residual
interphasic signature.
Nurse.
Bring me an
interphasic scanner.
I want to take a
closer look at this.
Commander...
I will have to confiscate
your sidearm.
Of course.
May I ask
a personal favor?
Yes.
Will you take care
of Spot for me?
Your animal.
I'm afraid if I have
another waking dream
I might injure him.
Of course.
Spot,
come here.
Unlike a canine...
Spot does not respond
to verbal commands.
( meowing )
Good-bye, Spot.
He will need to be
fed once a day.
He prefers Feline
Supplement number 25.
I understand.
And he will
require water.
And you must provide
him with a sandbox.
And you must
talk to him.
Tell him he is
a pretty cat
and a good cat...
I will feed him.
Perhaps that
will be enough.
( Worf sneezes, Spot meows )
Captain, we have
a problem.
Take a look at this.
Her tissue is breaking down
on the cellular level
and it's spreading.
At first I thought
it was a rash
from the coil brace
she was stabbed with,
but when I used the
interphasic scanner,
I found this.
PICARD:
what is it?
The question is...
what are they?
I've tested all
the medical staff
and I've found them
on almost
everyone so far.
The cellular decay
is accelerating
in all cases.
I haven't found
a way to stop it
or even slow it down.
Looks like you're
infected, too.
The organisms appear
to be attached
to our epidermal layers
with osmotic tendrils.
They're tapping directly
into the bloodstream
and from what I can tell,
they're spreading.
RIKER:
What are we dealing with here?
Are these creatures
feeding on us?
Yes, in a very
particular way.
They appear to be extracting
our cellular peptides.
It's roughly analogous
to the way terran leeches
consume hemoglobin.
If they're
not removed soon,
our bodies are going to lose
all their cellular cohesion.
We'll collapse into nothing
but a few pounds of chemicals.
All right. Is there any way that
we can affect these organisms?
We've tried EM radiation,
subspace fields,
thermal protons--
Nothing's worked.
They seem to exist in some sort
of interphasic state
just beyond
our range
of visual and
sensor acuity.
The only way we can see them
is to use an I.P. scanner.
Tricorders can't even
pick them up.
Do we know where these
things came from, Mr. Worf?
Well, I scanned the vicinity
with an I.P. scanner.
There was no sign
of any similar creatures
or any unusual
interphasic activity.
PICARD:
What about Mr. Data?
There must be
some connection
between his odd behavior
and these creatures.
Is he infested
as well?
No, I scanned him,
but I found nothing.
Data attacked
Counselor Troi
because he saw...
a mouth on her shoulder
and it was
in that same area
that we first saw
one of the organisms.
RIKER:
Data also saw
a straw in my head
and then Beverly discovered
an organism in the same place.
Those images are all part
of Data's dream.
Maybe somehow he's unconsciously
perceiving these creatures.
Then perhaps it is time
that we took a closer look
at Mr. Data's dreams.
It is an interesting
hypothesis.
If I am being
affected
by these interphasic
creatures
on an unconscious level,
it may also explain
my waking dreams
and my subsequent
antisocial behavior.
What we want to do,
Data,
is link your neural net
to the holodeck
and have you activate
your dream program
so as you dream,
we can observe
the dream images.
Perhaps we can learn more
about these creatures
by interpreting the symbols
and images of your dreams.
I see.
The concept is similar to
the method of directed dreaming.
Exactly. How soon
can you have the
link ready?
We'll need
about an hour
to establish all
the interface parameters.
Make it so.
In the meantime, Mr. Data,
I suggest that
you should prepare for bed.
I think we're ready,
Captain.
The link is active
and the holodeck
has been calibrated
to Data's neural net.
Ready,
Mr. Data?
Yes, sir.
Normally, I would
wish you pleasant dreams,
but in this case,
bad dreams would
be more helpful.
I understand, sir.
Initiating
dream program.
Stand by.
Let's be very
observant.
Even the most
insignificant image
could be a very
important symbol.
Right.
Here he comes.
Hello.
Can we speak
to Data directly
or would that
wake him up?
He should be
perceiving us
as just another part
of his dream.
Anything we say to him
will be taken
in that context.
You know, that sounds
like a telephone ringer,
but I don't see
a receiver.
( door opens )
Cake?
Oh, thank you.
Look at that.
Her right shoulder.
That is the same place
that Data stabbed her.
In his waking dream
he said that there was
a mouth on her shoulder.
They're both symbols
of consumption--
Mouth, food.
Mr. Data, what kind
of cake is this?
It is a cellular peptide
cake.
With mint frosting.
Cellular peptides?
That's exactly what the
creatures are extracting.
( phone ringing )
RIKER:
Will someone answer
that damn ringing?
( ringing gets louder )
Captain, the ringing
is getting worse.
What could the
ringing symbolize?
A bell?
A sound?
An old-fashioned way
of communicating?
Do you
want some?
It's delicious.
Will someone
please get that?
Yes?
It's for you.
Picard.
FREUD:
Kill them.
Kill who?
FREUD:
Kill them before it's too late.
Who is this?
I am
Dr. Sigmund Freud.
How does he fit
into all this?
If I were to interpret
my own appearance in this dream
I would say I am
the symbolic representation
of Data's unconscious mind
trying to warn him
about the dangers
he perceives around him.
You mean
the interphasic organisms?
Of course.
Tell me, Doctor,
how do we kill them?
( ringing begins )
Answer it.
Nein, nein!
Nein.
Do not be so literal.
When I say "answer it,"
I mean respond to it, to them.
( door opens )
Be quiet!
( groaning )
( grunting )
PICARD:
What do they represent?
I don't know,
but I do recognize
that junction
they're working on.
It's the plasma
conduit we installed
with the new
warp core.
Respond.
Respond to them?
What does
that mean?
What is it
that you're doing?
Go away.
Leave us alone.
Who are you?
We are...
...your enemies.
Stop!
You must not
hurt my friends.
( high-pitched shrieking )
Be quiet!
PICARD:
Data...
the shrieking noise
you made--
It causes them pain.
( shrieking continues )
Be... quiet!
( shrieking stops )
I believe I understand.
Geordi.
Yes, Data.
You must adjust
my positronic subprocessor
to emit
an interphasic pulse.
Data, what's
going on?
The workmen in my dreams
represent the organisms
which are trying
to demolish the ship.
The incessant ringing
of the telephone,
Dr. Freud's cautions
at the other end
were warnings
of the dangers around us.
What about the shrieking
noises that you made?
My positronic
subprocessor detected
high-frequency
interphasic signatures
from the organisms,
which are symbolically
represented in my dreams
by a high shriek.
When you made
those noises
the workmen
reacted in pain.
That is why
I have asked Geordi
to adjust
my subprocessor.
If I can produce a
high-frequency interphasic pulse
it may have a similar effect
on the creatures.
We're ready.
Picard to Sick Bay.
Beverly, we'll going to
be sweeping the ship
with a high-frequency
I.P. pulse.
Will you monitor
the creatures
for any reaction?
CRUSHER:
Understood.
( high-pitched shrieking begins)
( I.P. scanner whirring )
It's working,
Captain.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The creatures infesting
the Enterprise
have been completely
eliminated.
We believe
the infestation originated
within the warp core
we obtained on Starbase 84.
This conduit was manufactured
on Thanatos VII,
using a new interphasic
fusion process.
We think
it was that process
which attracted the organisms
to the conduit
where they lay dormant
until we activated
the warp core.
That's also why we couldn't
get the core on line.
The creatures were disrupting
the plasma flow.
How long before we have
warp power again?
Well, we're going to have
to manufacture a new conduit.
That's at least
six hours' work.
Six hours?
The banquet will be
completely over by then.
That's very
unfortunate.
I could try and
speed things up a bit.
No, no!
No. Uh...
I wouldn't want
to sacrifice
the safety
of the ship.
Understood, sir.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Counselor.
I did not have
a chance to apologize
for my actions.
Data...
don't worry about it.
Geordi explained
everything to me.
It wasn't
your fault.
But, somehow, I thought
turnabout would be fair play,
so... I made us a little
something to snack on.
I wonder...
What would Dr. Freud say
about the symbolism
of devouring oneself?
Data...
sometimes a cake
is just a cake.