Captain's Log,
Stardate 47254.1.
A delegation of the Cairn
have just come on board.
This telepathic species has
no concept of spoken language
and is being instructed
in its use by... an old friend.
I don't know what they'd
have done without me.
First, I had to learn
how they communicate.
Well, it was an absolutely
exhausting process.
It must have been.
Quite different from
Betazed telepathy.
We transmit words.
With the Cairn, it's,
uh... it's images--
a-a flood of them,
all at the same time.
It's overwhelming.
I can imagine.
Actually, it's
a very efficient way
of communicating.
If two Cairn were having
this conversation
it would have been
over minutes ago.
Really?
Of course, they realize
that they'll want to
communicate verbally
if they join
the Federation.
Oh, do me a favor.
Introduce yourself
to one of them.
Engage him
in conversation.
They need the practice.
I'd be happy to.
It's called a visor.
It enables
me to see.
Like my vocal enhancer.
It helps me
make sounds.
I see you've already
met my star pupil.
Hedril's picked up
spoken language
much faster
than the others.
It is often the case
that children
learn languages
more easily than adults.
Deanna was quite
good at languages
when she was little.
Where is Deanna?
Well, she must be here
somewhere.
Hedril, darling...?
What?
Um... go find
your father, dear.
I want to talk to him.
Mrs. Troi?
Oh, I'm just
a little tired.
This constant telepathy
with the Cairn...
um... no, I'm...
I'm fine, really.
Aren't you going
to mingle, Mr. Woof?
I do not care
for telepaths.
They make me...
uneasy.
Oh, don't worry.
The Cairn couldn't
read your thoughts
even if they wanted to.
Your brain isn't
sophisticated enough.
Neither
is yours, dear.
They can only communicate
with other telepaths.
Have either of you
seen Deanna?
She was working,
but she said she would be...
Speak of the devil.
Sorry I'm late.
I lost track
of the time.
Deanna dear,
come with me.
I want you to meet
the senior diplomat
of the Cairn delegation.
Maques, this is
the beautiful daughter
I've been telling
you about, Deanna.
Pleased to...
Hello.
Pleased to meet you.
Oh, yes...
that is it.
Pleased to meet
you, Deanna.
Good. Well, I'll just let
you young people chat.
Well, Maques
what do you think
of the Enterprise?
Oh...
it is beautiful.
Comfortable, also.
I'm glad you
think so.
Uh...
there is another word
that describes it.
But I cannot remember.
You've learned a great deal
in a very short time.
I'm sure it
won't be long
before your words do justice
to your thoughts.
Your mother...
told me...
of your need.
Need?
Uh, a moment.
Husband.
You need a husband.
I...
need a wife.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Oh, Deanna?
Oh... good morning.
So, what did you
think of Maques?
Why did you do that,
Mother?
You embarrassed
both of us.
Oh, he's really
very sweet.
And lonely, poor man.
A widower,
raising a child alone.
Mother, don't start.
I just think it's time
for you to settle down
and if your father
were still alive
I'm sure he'd
say the same thing.
Deck eight.
But you'll do exactly
what you want...
just like always.
Mother, stop it.
Are you coming?
What's wrong?
( sighs )
You are so
precious to me.
You're all I've got.
If something happened to you
I don't know what I'd do.
Nothing's going
to happen to me.
You'd better go.
My first appointment
isn't for a few minutes.
Why don't we talk
for awhile?
No, I'm fine.
I'm just tired from working
with the Cairn.
It's making me emotional.
Are you sure?
Mm-hmm. Go on.
I'll see you later.
Go on.
Maques.
I must... apologize...
for yesterday.
You don't have to.
My words...
they were... confused.
It wasn't your fault.
Please.
My mother misled you.
Not in everything.
She has...
an image of you
in her mind.
She shared it with me.
You are even
more beautiful.
The way my people
communicate...
it is... direct.
Nothing is hidden.
Yes?
Your mother is the first
to learn our telepathy.
You mean you've never
had telepathy
with someone
who wasn't Cairn?
No.
To communicate
with her is...
very different.
In what way?
Always, there is
a part of her that...
um...
a part of her
that is... dark.
Dark?
A part of her that...
cannot be seen.
Do you understand?
I'm not sure.
Have you asked my mother
about this?
Um...
she called it...
a moment.
Um... privacy.
Of course.
You said among the Cairn
nothing is hidden.
We value honesty,
but we don't always share
everything we're thinking
and feeling.
This is... privacy?
Yes.
It is... normal?
For us, yes.
If this
is your way...
I am relieved.
It is our way.
I will leave now.
I'm glad you
stopped by.
I'm glad to
have stopped also.
I was all set for another
round of arguing
when all of a sudden,
she just fell apart.
She's under
a lot of stress.
She's preparing the Cairn
to meet with
the Federation Council.
It's more than that.
I'm sensing some very
erratic emotions from her.
Even the clothes she's
wearing are unusual.
They're so subdued.
Maybe you just need
to sit and talk with her
for a minute.
LWAXANA:
Commander!
Take your hands
off her!
Mrs. Troi...
Don't you "Mrs. Troi" me!
Mother...
Why don't you leave
her alone?
If it weren't for you,
she'd be married by now!
That's enough.
Now, I am warning you--
stay away from my daughter!
You're coming
with me.
Oh, I don't know
what got into me.
Oh... please, tell Will
how sorry I am.
You're fine
but you're psilosynine
levels are a little low.
Psilo... hmm?
It's a neurotransmitter
involved in telepathy.
It's been depleted
by your work
with the Cairn.
You're going to
have to try to avoid
telepathic communication
for a while.
I can't.
Why?
We only have
three days left
and, uh...
oh, the Cairn have
so much to learn.
Lwaxana, I'm sorry
but you're going to have
to take some time and rest.
Maybe I can help
with the Cairn.
No, you're only
half Betazoid, dear.
And you have no experience
with their form of telepathy.
Then I won't use
telepathy.
We'll work verbally.
I suppose
we could do that.
And if they don't
understand something
I'll explain it to them
telepathically.
No, you'll work
verbally, too.
The point is for you
to get some rest, Mother.
Besides, it'll
do them good
to have to figure
things out with words.
I suppose you're right.
TROI:
This is the ship's
arboretum.
"Arbor" means tree.
Very good, Hedril.
This is where people
come to relax...
enjoy themselves
in a natural setting.
"Flowers of all hue
and without thorn,
the rose."
It's an old earth poem
by John Milton.
Please.
What is a... poem?
Poetry is an art form
that uses words
put together
in new and unexpected ways
sometimes in rhyme.
Milton was speculating
that in heaven
roses wouldn't have thorns.
Heaven?
Oh.
Oh, uh...
heaven is...
Well, it's, um...
How can
I put it?
Yes, I see.
Thank you.
"Heaven."
Mother, you're supposed
to be avoiding telepathy.
I'm only trying
to help, dear.
You don't look well.
I'm just tired.
Maybe I'll sit down.
Don't worry.
She'll be fine.
This is something
I think you'll
find interesting.
It's a jewel plant
from Folnar III.
The plant secretes
a resin...
( Hedril laughing )
...which is collected
within the blossom.
By the time
the bloom has faded
the resin has hardened into
a rare and beautiful gem.
Mother!
Mother...
Troi to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency
in the arboretum.
CRUSHER:
She's not responding
to cortical stimulation.
I'm not sure
what else I can do.
I don't understand.
She was fine
just yesterday.
It's so strange.
It's almost
as if her brain
has shut itself down.
Is there a
physiological cause?
I'm running
a subneural scan.
As far as I can see
there's no tissue damage
no neurochemical imbalance
no sign of infection,
nothing.
Yet her neural activity
is practically nonexistent.
The only exception
is in the paracortex.
Activity there
is almost off the scale.
The paracortex is
the Betazoid telepathic lobe.
She communicated with
Maques telepathically
just before she fell.
Might there be
some side effects
of Cairn telepathy of which
we're unaware?
It's a possibility.
I think it's time
that you and I had
a talk with Maques.
I am very...
apologetic
for what has happened
to your mother.
Maques, is it possible
that your telepathic
communications
with Mrs. Troi
harmed her in some way?
No.
I tried to...
to explain before.
Bad thoughts--
they hurt her.
TROI:
What thoughts?
Take your time.
Inside her.
The... dark place.
I don't understand.
She is...
um...
What are the words?
I don't
have the words.
( gasps )
Counselor?
Stop it.
It's all right.
I'm fine.
He was just trying
to communicate with me
telepathically.
Do you understand now?
I'm not sure.
He communicated
so much to me
that, at first, it was
just a jumble of images.
Have you been able
to sort any of it out?
I think so.
During his telepathic
contact with my mother
Maques sensed what he
calls "a dark place."
He tried to tell
me about it before
in my office, and
I misunderstood.
I thought he was
talking about
thoughts my mother
was keeping private
but what he meant
was that there
was something happening
in her metaconscious mind.
Metaconscious?
It's part of
the Betazoid psyche.
It's a kind of filtering
mechanism
that protects us
from psychic trauma.
Is Maques suggesting
that your mother's
metaconscious
has been somehow damaged?
He feels that whatever
is wrong with her
is centered there.
If he's right,
it may mean
that she's suffered
some kind of trauma
that her metaconscious
just can't tolerate.
Has your mother
mentioned anything
that happened to
her lately?
Something that might have
been traumatic for her?
No, nothing.
Maques could be wrong
about this.
There's still a chance
that a subneural scan
might be able to pinpoint
a physiological cause
for your mother's condition
something that
I might be able to treat.
The results won't be in
until morning.
Maybe we should all
try and get some rest.
I'd like to
stay here with her.
I'm going to try
and contact her
telepathically.
All right.
TROI:
Mother?
Can you hear me?
Please come back
to me.
Please.
LWAXANA ( weakly ):
Help me...
Mother?
Help... me.
How?
How can I help you?
Tell me, Mother.
Please.
( door opens, closes )
Computer, lights.
What are you doing?
Maques, what were you
doing in Sick Bay?
Helping.
Trying...
to help Lwaxana.
How? What were you
trying to do?
I was...
She was...
You, Deanna.
Maybe you.
Yes?
You must...
How can I explain?
Tell me telepathically.
Maques believes
my mother's psyche has
collapsed in on itself--
that for some reason
she has retreated
into her metaconscious mind.
Was he trying to contact
her telepathically?
Yes. He was able
to access images
being generated
by her metaconscious
but he couldn't make
any sense of them.
I did not...
understand.
He saw faces
he didn't recognize
events he couldn't
interpret.
If we could decipher
these images
we might be
able to determine
whether or not your
mother's condition
was induced by
a traumatic event.
Maques feels he can provide
a telepathic bridge
that would allow me to access
my mother's metaconscious.
If he can,
I might be able
to find out
what happened to her.
And if you succeed,
can you use that
information
to help your mother?
I'm not sure
but I do know
that there's a part of her
that wants to be helped.
When I tried to contact
her telepathically
I heard a voice
calling out to me.
If your mother's psyche
has collapsed in on itself
could accessing her mind
pose any danger to you?
There's no way to know.
I'd like to try.
I'll be monitoring her
throughout
the entire procedure.
If anything
goes wrong
Maques can break
the telepathic link.
Your mother, part of her
is very frightened.
She may...
resist you.
I understand.
( canine growling )
LWAXANA ( weakly ):
Help me.
Mother?
( canine snarling )
( liquid splashing )
PICARD:
Counselor,
can you hear me?
Captain?
Deanna, Dr. Crusher
has become concerned
that your paracortical
readings have become erratic.
Are you talking to me
from Sick Bay?
Yes. I want you to sever your
connection to your mother.
Why don't you
ask Maques to do it?
I'm asking you.
That is an order,
Counselor.
You're not
Captain Picard.
( Lwaxana's voice ):
Leave me alone, please.
( canine growling )
( gasps )
( growling )
This isn't real.
None of this
is real.
( snarling )
( breathing heavily )
Deanna?
Daddy?
Look at you.
You've become
a beautiful woman.
Don't do this.
I'm sorry I had to go away
when you were so little.
I didn't want to.
You're not my father.
You're part of
my mother's mind.
What is this place?
This is our house near
Lake El-Nar on Betazed.
We used to live here.
Deanna, let's not
waste this chance.
I want to hear
everything about you.
Did I live here?
For a while,
when you were a baby.
You were such
a beautiful baby.
Your mother and I
loved you so much.
I don't
remember these toys.
I bet you don't
remember me
singing you to sleep at
night either, but I did.
I do remember.
I always felt safe
when you sang to me.
There was one song you
always asked me to sing.
You couldn't fall asleep
unless you heard it.
"Down in the Valley."
Yes.
♪ Down
in the valley ♪
♪ Valley so low ♪
♪ Hang your
head over ♪
♪ Hear
the wind blow... ♪
No. You're just trying
to keep me here...
keep me from
finding something.
Your mother doesn't
want to see you, Deanna.
I have to help her.
If you want to
help her, leave.
Let her have peace.
She called out
to me.
She does
want me to help.
Stay with me--
just a little while.
Deanna, it's been so long.
We'll never have
this chance again.
Good-bye, Daddy.
( liquid gurgling )
Hedril.
Mother.
Get away from here!
No!
Hedril, I asked your father
to bring you here
because I wanted to talk
to you about something.
You know that Lwaxana
is sick, don't you?
Yes.
Is it my fault?
No, not at all.
But I believe that she's
been thinking about you.
Do you know why?
I make her sad.
Why do you
say that?
Because it's true.
Do you have any idea
why Hedril would
make my mother sad?
No.
Well, thank you for
coming to talk to us.
I'll see you later,
all right?
Counselor, I hope your
mother gets better.
Thank you, Hedril.
So do I.
I just don't understand
how she fits into all this.
And I haven't found
a physiological cause
for what's happened
to your mother--
which makes me feel
that Maques was right
when he said your mother's
condition
was precipitated
by a traumatic event.
Could this event
have involved Hedril?
I don't think so.
My mother never
mentioned her.
Does your mother keep
personal logs or a journal?
Yes, she does.
I'll contact
Mr. Homn on Betazed
and ask him to transmit
a copy as soon as possible.
There may be some
clues there.
Perhaps we are
being too literal.
I have recently
learned in my study
of dream analysis
that people who
appear in a dream
can sometimes represent
different aspects
of the person
who is dreaming.
That's right!
A child might
represent vulnerability.
Hedril may depict some fragile
part of my mother.
The part
that she's protecting.
You said that everything
you encountered
when you were in her mind
was a barrier
of one kind or another.
Yes-- you, the wolf,
my father...
It was as though
she were
summoning all
her defenses to keep me away.
But keep me away
from what?
What is she protecting?
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Counselor.
Hello, Captain.
I've just come
from Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher feels
that your mother's
condition is worsening.
Her neural foundations
are getting weaker.
Have you had
any luck here?
No, nothing.
I've gone through
all her belongings.
I've read her journal for
the last five years.
And, other than the fact
that I'm not married yet
nothing bad seems to have
happened to her.
Is this your father?
Yes.
He had a kind face.
I remember when he died
my mother had to go
through all his things
and pack them away.
I was seven.
I remember thinking
how mad he'd be
when he came home
and saw what she'd done.
I didn't understand
he wasn't coming back.
Deanna, your mother might
still come out of this.
If we can't figure out
what's wrong with her, Captain
I don't think she will.
But I don't know
what else to do.
I've talked with Mr. Homn,
who's known her for years.
I've checked her
medical records.
I've made inquiries to
the government on Betazed.
I've contacted her
closest friends.
If she's been through some
kind of psychic trauma
there's just
no evidence of it.
You say that you've
reviewed her journals
for the past five years.
Maybe we should
go further back.
That's a lot to review.
My mother's kept
a journal
since before
she was married.
Then let's start
at the beginning.
( sighs )
First entry seems to be
stardate 30620.1.
That's the year
they were married.
Hmm. That's odd.
There's a seven-year gap.
It starts about a year
after the wedding.
If I'm not mistaken,
it ends
a few months
after your birth.
My mother's so diligent
about her journal.
Why would she have stopped
making entries for so long?
She didn't.
The files were
deleted...
by your mother
almost
30 years ago.
I don't understand
any of this.
Captain, I have to go back
inside my mother's mind.
It's the only way we're ever
going to get any answers.
Thank you.
Deanna, you understand
that if your paracortical
readings get too high again
I'm going to tell Maques
to sever the connection?
I know.
( wolf growling )
Hedril, be careful!
Who is Hedril?
Wait!
I want to talk to you.
LWAXANA:
Help me.
Help me!
( water gurgling )
( footsteps )
LWAXANA:
Go.
Mother?
Go away.
No.
I want to help you.
Why did you delete
parts of your journal?
Did something
happen to you
you don't want me
to know about?
Leave me alone,
please.
Who's Hedril, Mother?
Why is she here?
Is Hedril me, when
I was a little girl?
No.
Oh, no.
I'd never let anything
happen to you, never.
Did you let something
happen to someone?
Was it here,
at El-Nar?
You were just a baby.
Tell me.
Whatever it is, we
can face it together.
I can't, I can't.
You can.
We can.
GIRL:
Help me.
Help me, Papa.
Here.
Please, don't make me
go through this again.
Now hold on
to him.
Don't let
him run off.
I will.
Mommy, can we go play
by the water?
No, Kestra, stay
here with us.
Please.
( crying )
Kestra.
Oh, Kestra, you've
made the baby cry.
Kestra?
No, don't cry,
Deanna.
Don't cry.
Mommy's here.
Mommy, please.
No, Kestra.
We're going to eat
in just a few minutes.
LWAXANA:
Here, what's wrong?
What's wrong,
little one?
Tell Mommy what's wrong.
Oh, Ian.
Ian, she's teething.
Uh, where's
her ring?
( dog snarling )
No, no, I don't want
to see this again.
I can't.
What happened, Mother?
What happened next?
I don't remember.
You have to.
You can't
hold it back.
It's killing you.
The dog got away.
She ran after it.
We didn't notice.
( sobbing )
Oh, why?
Why did I look away?
Why wasn't
I paying attention?
You have to forgive
yourself, Mother.
You have
to let it go.
How can I?
I let her die.
It was
a terrible tragedy--
the worst thing
that can happen
to any parent.
I know you
feel responsible,
but it was an accident.
And what you're doing
isn't fair to Kestra.
I saw
a little girl
who was sweet and happy.
She must have brought
a great deal of joy
to your lives.
Every morning,
she woke up with...
with a smile.
Isn't it better to
remember her like that?
I just found out
I had a sister I never knew.
I'd like to learn what
was good
and joyous about her
to celebrate her life,
not mourn it.
How?
How can I do that?
Kestra was here
a few moments ago.
Talk to her.
No. No.
Do it, Mother.
Tell her
how you feel.
I'll be here
with you.
I'll help you.
KESTRA:
Mommy.
Kestra.
Oh, Kestra.
My precious one.
I'm so sorry.
( sobbing )
I have to go now.
I know.
I remember the day
I took this.
Mr. Homn said he saved it
in case someday you
wanted to remember her.
( sighs )
I wish you could have
known her, Deanna.
I wish you two could have
grown up together.
Tell me about her.
I want to know
everything.