Captain's Log,
Stardate 47304.2.
The Enterprise has arrived
at Kesprytt III
in order to evaluate an unusual
request on the part of the Kes
for associate membership
in the Federation.
This morning,
she was 15 minutes late.
That's the third time
this week.
( tapping )
Jean-Luc.
You don't have
the slightest idea
what I'm talking
about, do you?
No. I'm really sorry.
I don't.
I've been telling you
about Nurse Ogawa
and Ensign Markson
for the last 15 minutes.
You have?
Mm-hmm.
I'm really sorry.
Are you worried about
this mission with the Kes?
Not worried, exactly.
This notion of admitting
half their planet
while leaving
the other half out...
First of all, the Kes
are not half the planet.
They're nearly 3/4 of it.
And the Prytt are
not being left out.
They themselves
simply don't want
to have contact
with anyone
from the outside--
not the Federation
or anyone else.
Every member of the Federation
entered as a unified world,
and that unity said
something about them--
that they had resolved
certain social and
political differences
and they were now ready
to become part of
a larger community.
By all indications
the Kes are a very unified,
very progressive people.
But the Prytt are not.
They're reclusive
to the point of xenophobia.
Well, think about Earth.
What if one of
the old nation states--
say, Australia,
had decided not to join
the world government
in 2150?
Would that have disqualified
us as a Federation member?
That analogy is not...
Riker to captain.
Go ahead, Number One.
We've received word
from Ambassador Mauric,
he's ready to see you
and Dr. Crusher.
Inform him
we're on our way.
Thank you for breakfast.
Wait until tomorrow.
I have something
very special planned.
It's a Vulcan dish,
that's all I'll say.
Captain, doctor.
I have the coordinates
of Ambassador Mauric's
chambers.
Let's not keep them
waiting, Mr. Worf.
Enterprise to Kes
Security Relay Station One.
We are ready
to commence transport.
Acknowledged, Enterprise.
We have lowered
our defense shield.
Confirmed.
Energize.
MALE:
This is Security
Relay Station One.
We are ready to receive your
captain and medical officer.
This is the Enterprise.
We have already completed
the transport sequence.
You should have them.
Negative, Enterprise.
They're not here.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
Beverly.
What happened?
I don't know.
The last thing
I remember,
we were beginning
to transport.
I assume we must
be on Kesprytt
and we're in some
kind of prison cell.
The question is why?
I can't imagine
that Ambassador Mauric
would have any reason to detain
us.
Jean-Luc...
What is it?
Let me see.
What?
It looks like
an implant.
Seems to be connected
directly to the brain stem.
Is it some kind
of coercive device?
Whatever it is I doubt
it's designed for our health.
What is
going on here?
If you could tell us
why you've taken us
hostage, we might be able...
You are not hostages.
You are prisoners.
Prisoners on
whose authority?
You're being held
under the authority
of the Prytt
security ministry.
The charges are conspiring
with the enemy.
Enemy?
You mean the Kes.
We are not fools.
We are aware of
the Federation attempt
to establish a military
alliance with the Kes.
It will not be tolerated.
Your information
is incorrect.
We have no plans...
There is no point
in trying to
mislead us, captain.
The devices
which have been implanted
in your cerebral cortexes
will soon be calibrated
to your psi-wave pattern.
At that time we will
be able to get all
the information we need.
And then you'll
discover that we are
telling the truth.
We shall see.
There is nothing wrong
with the transporter.
I have run
a complete diagnostic
of all of the targeting
components.
Then what happened
to the captain
and Dr. Crusher?
Commander,
the transporter
sensor log
shows an unusual
concentration
of antigraviton particles
in the emitter coil.
A concentration
of antigraviton particles
suggests a tractor beam.
It might have deflected
the transporter beam
to a different set
of coordinates.
Is there a way to locate
those coordinates?
The tractor beam
originated
somewhere in
the Prytt Alliance.
What does the Prytt want with
Captain Picard and Dr. Crusher?
I don't know,
and it's not going
to be easy to find out.
The Prytt have
consistently refused
all outside contact.
We're going to have
to work through the Kes.
Contact
Ambassador Mauric.
Tell him I want
a meeting right now.
Aye, sir.
What?
You're staring at me.
I was just thinking about
how to get out of here.
There may be
a structural flaw
that would allow us
to escape.
Right.
Beverly,
the important thing
during any confinement
is to think positively,
and not give up hope.
There is a way
out of every box--
a solution
to every puzzle.
It's just a matter
of finding it.
Damn!
Well, at least this means
we won't starve to death.
It means they plan on
keeping us here for awhile.
I'm beginning to think
negatively, Jean-Luc.
My tricorder.
Does it work?
Yes.
Except something's been added
to the main directory.
It's a map.
An escape route.
That guard must be
working for the Kes.
Possibly,
but it could be
part of a very
carefully laid trap.
Well, if you ask me,
I'd like to take
my chances out there.
Agreed.
Is there a way
to open the cell door?
Yes. The code's
been entered.
Commander, on behalf
of my government
I would like to take
this opportunity
to present
my profound apologies
regarding this
unfortunate incident.
That's very kind,
Ambassador,
but I don't think
anyone here holds you
or the Kes government
responsible
for what happened.
Our primary concern
is not to assign blame
but to recover
our missing officers.
I agree.
We are prepared to insert
a hostage rescue team
into the Prytt capital city
on three hours' notice.
Ambassador, we have
not even attempted
a diplomatic effort yet.
I would rather not use force
until we've exhausted
all other options.
I don't believe there is any
diplomatic option, Commander.
We have no formal relations
with the Prytt, no ambassadors.
There's simply no way
to contact them.
Surely, you must have
some means of communication
in case
of a planetary emergency.
We have never had need
of such a system.
We can determine their
communications frequencies
and establish a link.
Allow me
to be blunt.
The Prytt are a fanatical,
xenophobic people
with little regard
for civilized discourse.
Even if you do establish
a communications
link with them
it will be a complete
waste of time.
How long has it been
since your last
diplomatic contact?
Humph!
Almost a century.
Then it's possible they may
have changed over the years.
We have had other less...
formal contacts with the Prytt--
contacts
we cannot discuss--
but I can assure you,
they have changed
very little.
RIKER:
With all due respect,
Ambassador,
I think I should try to
communicate with the Prytt
before I sanction
the use of force.
Of course, Commander.
In the meantime,
I will continue
making preparations
for a rescue mission.
Agreed.
I do have one request.
We believe that the Prytt
obtained their information
about the transport of
your captain and doctor
through a breach of our
communications network.
If I could establish
a base of operations
here on the Enterprise,
I'd feel much more secure.
Mr. Worf will help you.
Thank you.
Lieutenant.
You first.
( sighing )
Is there a problem,
Ambassador?
Probably not.
Simply securing the area.
I can assure you
there is no need.
I'm sure you're right.
Yes, this will do
very nicely.
As security chief
of the Enterprise,
I would be glad to assist
you in any way possible.
There's no need.
We'll take care
of everything.
Thank you,
Lieutenant.
There must be
a lava flow
or an underground
hot spring
somewhere near here.
It's a lava flow.
It's about
30 meters below us.
It says we should
go this way.
I smell gas.
This whole chamber
is filled with pockets
of a methanogenic compound.
Can we get
through it?
I think so.
What did you say?
I didn't say anything.
There might be
a fairly regular pattern
to these eruptions.
We should be able
to navigate our way
through them
if we're careful.
Say when.
Now.
The eruptions
have stopped.
( beeping loudly )
The gas is building up.
I have scanned the entire
Prytt communications system.
This appears to be the
primary access module
for their
central government.
Can you determine which
of the com links is connected
to the prime minister's
office?
I believe so, sir.
However, the Prytt
have no link designed
for extraterritorial
communications.
Our hail may come as
quite a surprise to them.
Well, they're going
to have to adjust.
Open a channel.
This is Prime Minister
Horath's headquarters.
How can I be of service?
This is Commander
William T. Riker,
Federation Starship
Enterprise.
I know this may seem
an unusual way...
The Enterprise?
You mean the ship in orbit?
That's right.
Why are you
on this com link?
We're having trouble contacting
your government directly.
We had to start somewhere.
If you would
let me talk to...
Did you get authorization
for this communication
from the security ministry?
As I said, we're having
trouble contacting your...
I cannot participate in
an unauthorized communication.
This transmission
is terminated.
Not very friendly,
are they?
No, sir.
( beeping )
Sir,
we are being hailed.
It is the Prytt
security council.
Well, it looks like we got
someone's attention.
On screen.
Enterprise, this is
Security Minister Lorin.
You will immediately cease
all attempts
at communication
with our people.
Minister, we have been
attempting
to contact someone
in your government.
It appears that
you have detained
two of our officers.
We would like to discuss
the situation.
There is nothing
to discuss.
If you do not terminate
these transmissions,
we will be forced
to take aggressive action
against your ship.
Their weapon systems
pose no threat
to the Enterprise.
Just the same,
let's keep the shields up
for the time being.
Aye, sir.
Is there a problem,
Commander?
Our effort with the Prytt
just ran into a wall.
I'm sorry, but perhaps this
will brighten your spirits.
We have freed
your captain and doctor.
What?
They were being held
in a prison just outside
the Prytt capital
but one of our operatives was
able to arrange their escape.
Where are they now?
Well, they should be
en route to the Kes border.
Our operative provided them
with a detailed map
and instructions
on where to go.
How will you get them
across the border?
At the moment,
that information
is confidential,
but trust us--
we do have a plan.
Ambassador, I'm afraid
I must insist
that you provide us
with more information.
Oh, I understand
your concern, of course,
but I would feel
more comfortable
discussing these
operational details
in a less public
environment.
Certainly, we can step
into the ready room.
I would prefer the quarters
you provided me.
They're safer.
All right.
( tricorder beeping )
There's no way
out of here.
Maybe we took
a wrong turn.
So am I.
What?
I'm thirsty, too.
I didn't say anything
about being thirsty.
I heard you.
You said,
"I'm very thirsty."
I was thinking about it,
but I didn't say anything.
You were thinking it?
The transceivers.
Lorin said that they would
align themselves
to our psi-wave patterns.
The implants must be
transmitting our thoughts.
What am I thinking?
I don't know.
I can't hear your
thoughts either.
Well, maybe
it was a fluke.
Well, right now, we have
more immediate concerns.
Does your map show us
a way out of here?
Yes.
We need to go up.
There's a ledge
about 30 meters up.
That should lead
to another tunnel
that connects up
to the surface.
Right.
I heard that.
They weren't words
exactly--
a sudden sense of...
fear.
A sense of fear
of heights.
So much for that
being a fluke.
It was a strange sensation,
suddenly having these thoughts
appear in my mind.
If you sensed a fear of heights,
you sensed pretty accurately.
Come on.
You've done this before.
It's just like on the holodeck.
One step at a time.
Just climbing,
steadily and slowly.
Right.
( door opens )
I see you've done
some redecorating.
Just a few pieces of equipment
necessary for security reasons.
You understand?
Certainly.
He is, uh...
all right.
How do you plan
to get our people
out of Prytt territory?
You must realize
that everything
I'm about to say
cannot leave this room.
For some time, we have
had certain... friends
among the Prytt--
citizens who realize
that the long struggle
between our two peoples
can only end when
the Prytt government
is made to see reason.
You've recruited
a few Prytt spies.
That's a crude
but accurate term.
These friends
will be waiting
for your captain
and doctor
when they reach
the village
of Ohn-kor, near
the Kes border.
The map we provided
your officers
will take them
to a tavern there.
Forgive me, Ambassador,
but is it wise to send
two human fugitives
in Starfleet uniforms
into a Prytt village?
The danger is minimal.
Our operatives control
almost the whole village.
Once contact has been
made with Captain Picard
and Dr. Crusher
our friends will escort them
across the border into Kes.
I would still feel better
if they could rendezvous
with your operatives
in a less public place.
Commander, I assure you,
we know what we're doing.
We've had a great deal
of experience
in dealing
with the Prytt.
We would hardly risk
the safety of your people.
After all, we still hope
that you will recommend
our entrance
into the Federation.
One of us is hungry.
That would be me.
Would you mind thinking
of something else?
You're making me hungry.
What do you want me
to think about?
Something other
than a large bowl
of vegetable soup.
My grandmother
used to make it
with peas, carrots...
Beverly!
I'm sorry.
I am not being
unreasonable.
I didn't say
that you were.
I may have thought it,
but there's a difference.
You're right.
We can't react to
every random thought
that crosses the
other person's mind.
( tricorder beeping )
Isn't it
astonishing, though,
how much clutter there is
in the consciousness?
Odd memories coming
to the surface,
bits of half-
remembered songs.
Stray daydreams,
scattered minutiae.
I wonder how true telepaths
sift through it all.
How can they really get
to what someone's thinking
if the mind keeps churning
all this flotsam
to the surface?
That is not funny.
I wanted to see if you
were still listening.
I think our link
is getting stronger.
Maybe if we put some
distance between us
that might weaken it.
Not that I'm growing
tired of hearing
your most intimate thoughts.
Certainly not.
Jean-Luc...
What happened?
Oh...
I was suddenly overcome
with a wave of nausea.
Me, too.
Hmm...
there's nothing wrong
with either of us.
Maybe the air is toxic.
Oh...
( gasping )
Oh, same thing.
But when you moved back
to me, it got better.
Well, it seems
as if we're... stuck
with each other.
What is it?
I'm not sure
whether we should go
over this hill or that one.
The topography on this map
is a little vague.
Let me see.
This way.
You don't really know,
do you?
What?
I mean, you're acting
like you know
exactly which way to go
but you're only guessing.
Do you do this
all the time?
No, but there are times
when it is necessary
for a captain to
give the appearance
of confidence.
I... I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
I just couldn't resist.
I'm beginning to realize
that you always seem to have
some acerbic remark on
the tip of your tongue.
Well, at least
I've trained myself
not to say it anymore.
When I was a little girl
my mouth was always
landing me in trouble
with my parents,
my teachers...
And your friends.
There was someone
called Tom Norris?
That's right.
I had one date with him
which I brought
to an abrupt halt
with the words,
"Is that a beard...
BOTH:
...or is your face dirty?"
There's something more.
You're laughing,
but actually
you were embarrassed
by that incident.
Yes.
I thought I was being cute,
but I really hurt him.
That was a long time ago.
I learned
a valuable lesson.
This sharing of thoughts
and feelings is...
quite compelling.
Very.
We'd better get going.
I don't think so either.
Maybe we can find
another way
to reach the village.
No. It's several
kilometers
to find another way
around that ridge.
The border is just
two kilometers east of here.
There's a force-field
protecting it,
but we can find
some way to deal with that
when we get there.
Come on.
All right.
Something wrong?
Have a seat.
Captain Picard
and Dr. Crusher
did not show up
at the designated
rendezvous point.
Do you know
what happened to them?
No. We have no idea what
happened to them.
We find it strange
that your officers
should follow the escape plan
so precisely and then fail
to make the crucial rendezvous
with our operative.
Well, it is possible
they have been recaptured.
Our sources would have
informed us instantly
if that had happened.
Of course, if they
weren't captured...
if they simply made
a different rendezvous...
we might not ever
know about it.
A different rendezvous?
I'm not sure I know
what you mean.
Of course not.
How could you know
if your captain and doctor
were meeting secretly
with the Prytt?
Meeting in order to set up
a military alliance
with the Federation?
What?
It was a clever scheme.
First, you pretend
to lose your officers
during transport.
Then you ask us for help
and get us to expose
several of our undercover
operatives in the process,
but what you didn't
expect was for us
to get your people
out of prison so quickly.
They needed more time,
they needed more time
to plot the destruction
of the Kes
with their new
Prytt friends.
This is ridiculous.
You're beginning to see
conspiracies everywhere.
We were invited here
by the Kes.
Why would we ally ourselves
with the Prytt?
Indeed, why?
Ah... you can believe
what you like.
We're going to find our people
with or without your help.
Then I believe
it is time for us
to be leaving
the Enterprise.
Fine.
Make sure you take
all this junk with you.
No luck?
( sighs )
I'm beginning to think
there's not a single thing
on this planet we can eat.
Well, by this time
tomorrow
we could be back
on board the Enterprise
and you can plant yourself
in front of a replicator
with a knife and fork.
Remember that Vulcan dish
I promised for breakfast?
Well, I was just...
You hate having
breakfast with me.
That's not true.
Yes, it is.
When I said breakfast,
I heard you say,
"I hate that."
That's not quite
what I meant.
Well, then
what did you mean?
It's just that
I don't like...
What I've been choosing
for breakfast recently.
You see,
I think that breakfast
should be a simple meal
and recently,
you've been ordering
these elaborate things.
Coffee and croissants.
That's all you really
want, isn't it?
Coffee and croissants.
Well, why didn't you
just say so?
I didn't think
it was important.
You don't like those
elaborate meals either.
No. I usually prefer
something simple myself,
but I thought you might
enjoy more variety.
Well...
I guess it's coffee
and croissants
for both of us
from now on.
BOTH:
I love firelight.
There's something
about the flame,
the smell of the smoke,
which always
seemed to me to be...
intoxicating somehow.
I remember when Jack
and I took Wesley
on his first camping
trip to Balfour Lake.
Wesley kept throwing
manta leaves
into the fire,
watching them pop.
Jack kept telling him...
What?
Jean-Luc, I heard you.
Don't push it away.
When I said,
"Jack and I",
I felt this sudden
wave of... something.
I didn't know
you felt that way.
Didn't you?
I... I guess I always
knew that there was...
an attraction
between us right from
the start, but...
I never knew
how strongly you felt.
Why didn't you ever tell me
you were in love with me?
You were married
to my best friend.
At first,
I thought it was...
harmless infatuation--
something... hormonal
rather than emotional.
Then, when the months
went by
and the three of us
began spending
more time together...
I realized that
it was something else,
and it wasn't right.
But although...
I would never act on it
I couldn't help
the way I felt.
And when Jack died,
you felt guilty.
I felt guilty
before he died...
having feelings like that
for my best friend's wife...
and then later,
after the accident...
I promised myself
that I would never
tell you how I felt.
It would be like
betraying my friend.
That's why you
didn't want me
on the Enterprise
seven years ago.
I didn't know
how I would react.
( sighing )
And then...
little by little,
I realized that I...
I didn't have
those feelings anymore.
20 years is, after all,
a long time.
And now we're friends.
Yes, friends.
Well...
we still have
a lot of ground
to cover tomorrow.
We should get
some sleep.
Right.
Ambassador,
thank you for coming.
Commander.
We're going to clear up
this misunderstanding
once and for all.
Hail Minister Lorin,
please.
Aye, sir.
Enterprise,
I have warned you
about these unauthorized
communications.
Yes, I know,
but I think it's about time
we all sat down together
and tried to work this out.
I have Ambassador
Mauric here...
That is your misfortune.
We have nothing to say
to either of you.
MAURIC:
Commander, you're
working with the Prytt.
Putting on
this little show
for my benefit does
neither of us any good.
We'll see.
Mr. Worf?
I believe there's someone
waiting for us
in the observation lounge.
I should have known
anyone willing to deal
with the Kes
would be capable
of such an outrage.
I'm sorry to resort to such
drastic measures, Minister,
but you left me
little choice.
Don't pretend the two
of you are enemies.
It's too late
for charades.
If that is
an attempt to hide
your military alliance
with the Federation
you needn't bother.
I already know far more
than you can imagine.
Let's all just sit down
and try to find out
what happened to Captain
Picard and Dr. Crusher.
I will not sit
at a table with him.
No more than
I would sit with her.
All right,
then we'll stand.
The important thing is
that we start talking.
I am not authorized to
talk with a Kes official.
All right, then,
you talk to me.
Where are
my officers?
As if you don't know
already.
Let's go.
I'm all right.
We are already
aware of your plan
to use Federation
technology
to build new
attack satellites.
You will find that
we are prepared for them.
That is an interesting
but pointless lie.
I'd rather discuss
your own plans
to use Federation aid
to stage a takeover
of Kolrod Island.
We have been
over this before.
Kolrod clearly belongs
to the Prytt,
who originally...
RIKER:
That's it!
I can see that diplomacy
is not going
to get us anywhere today,
and I do not have time
to negotiate,
so let's put all of
our cards on the table.
You're concerned
that the Kes
are going to be admitted
to the Federation.
Correct.
As first officer
of the Enterprise
I think I can promise you
that is not going to happen.
The Kes will be
denied membership.
You have no authority
to make that decision.
Despite whatever games
you played with the Prytt
when you arrived,
we still plan
to take our petition
directly to
the Federation Council.
They'll listen.
They will also listen
to the reports
of the captain
of the Enterprise
and his first officer.
And I can tell you
right now
the first officer's report
will go something like this:
Kesprytt,
a deeply troubled world--
social, political,
military problems
that they have yet
to resolve.
The Kes, while a friendly
and democratic people,
are driven by suspicion,
deviousness and paranoia.
It is the opinion
of this officer
that they are not ready
for membership.
Now...
...the matter of
our missing officers.
They're still charged
with spying, Commander.
I have heard nothing here
which would alter that.
Then maybe you should
consider this.
If anything happens to them
Starfleet is going to want
a full investigation,
which means more starships
will be coming to Kesprytt
and those ships are
going to want answers,
which puts your country
under a very large
and very uncomfortable
microscope.
Remember how
unhappy you were
when we contacted just
one of your people
without authorization?
Well, just think what
it'll be like--
ten starships
asking questions,
contacting hundreds
of your people--
massive sensor sweeps.
They may even start
sending down away teams
all because you wouldn't help me
find my missing officers.
I think I can use
the tricorder
to set up
a multiphase pulse.
That should weaken
the force-field enough
to let us through.
No, no, the modulation
frequency
is in the upper
harmonic range.
Right.
They're coming.
I'm working
as fast as I can.
Minister, we have
the human female.
The male is standing
in Kes territory.
Very well. Transmit
their coordinates
to the Enterprise
transporter room.
Understood.
Thank you, Minister.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Mauric is determined
to take his protest
to the Federation Council,
but I don't think
he'll get very far.
I tend to agree,
Number One.
( chuckling )
( laughing )
Did I miss something?
Of course,
of course.
You're
absolutely right.
Ah...
That was wonderful.
My pleasure.
Don't get me wrong,
Jean-Luc,
but I'm glad we're not
joined at the hip any longer.
So, were you getting
tired of my company?
Just tired of
bumping into you
every 30 seconds.
I was beginning to feel
as if you were
part of my uniform.
To freedom.
Freedom.
Penny
for your thoughts.
I was just thinking that,
as distracting as it was,
I was beginning to get used
to hearing your thoughts
and I find that I miss it.
So do I.
It was very intimate.
You know...
last night
I couldn't sleep.
Oh?
I was awake
for several hours
and, thanks
to the implants,
I got to hear
some very interesting
dreams of yours.
A man cannot be
held responsible
for what his mind does
while he's asleep.
What about
when he's awake?
So, now that we've had
this unique experience,
what do we do?
What do you mean?
You know
exactly what I mean.
No, I don't.
The implants have been
removed, remember?
Now that we know
how each of us feels,
perhaps we should not be
afraid to explore
those feelings.
Or perhaps
we should be afraid.
I think I should be
going now.
Good night.