( Spot yowling )
Geordi?
In here, Data.
Got her now.
She's trapped.
Come on out of there,
you ungra...
( Spot snarls )
Hey, hey,
don't you spit at me.
Why is Spot
under the bed?
Probably because she knows
if I catch her
I'm going to kill her.
Has Spot been misbehaving?
So far, she's broken a vase
a teapot
she's ruined
one of my chairs
using it
as a scratch post
and she's coughing hair balls up
all over my carpet.
These incidents are common
to cat owners.
When you borrowed Spot, you said
you wanted to experience
the full range
of feline behavior
before getting a cat yourself.
Yeah, well, I'm not ready.
You can take her back
with my blessings.
Go ahead, call her.
Spot does not respond
to verbal commands.
She doesn't come
when you call her?
Data...
have you ever considered
training this cat?
I never found it
to be necessary.
Necessary? Data,
the cat is out of control.
Half the time, I didn't know
if she was going lick me
or scratch my face off.
I have never experienced
this kind of behavior in Spot.
Although she does have
the unfortunate habit
of jumping on my computer
console when I am working.
She needs training.
Riker to senior staff.
Please report
to the Observation Lounge.
Mission briefing
in ten minutes.
All right, we have to get
her out of here.
I'll scare her, you grab her
when she comes out, okay?
I do not think it would be
wise to startle her.
( Geordi yells, Spot yowls )
( metallic crash )
Training... definitely.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47310.2.
We are investigating
the disappearance
of the medical transport
Fleming
somewhere
in the Hekaras Corridor.
Our search is complicated
by the unique properties
of this particular
region of space.
The Fleming last contacted
Starfleet four days ago.
According to them, there was
nothing out of the ordinary
when they entered the corridor.
Data.
The unusually intense
tetryon field in this sector
poses a severe
navigational hazard
to warp-driven vessels.
The Hekaras Corridor
is the only route in this sector
which is free of tetryon fields.
Ships traveling at warp
must use the corridor
to ensure safe passage
through the region.
How long will it take
to complete
a level-1 search?
At least two days, sir.
The corridor is over
12 light-years long
and the surrounding
tetryon interference
will limit our sensor range.
Could we send out
reconnaissance probes
to supplement the sensors?
LA FORGE:
Won't be very effective.
The interference will
make it difficult
to maintain contact
with the probes.
Best we can do is to
increase sensor efficiency.
We've installed
multiphase buffers
on all the sensor
modules, Captain.
It should help
a little.
Hekaras II is inhabited,
isn't it?
Maybe they've had
contact with the Fleming.
They haven't.
I've already spoken
to the Hekaran government.
According to them, only one ship
has passed through the system
in the last week.
It was a Ferengi trader.
The Fleming  was carrying
a supply of rare biomimetic gel
which is very valuable.
Is it possible
that the Ferengi
might have hijacked it?
I wouldn't put it past them.
I think we should prepare
for that contingency.
I agree.
All right then.
Mr. Worf, initiate
your search pattern.
Let's head in.
DATA:
Geordi?
There has been
a slight drop
in sensor
efficiency.
Perhaps we should examine
the phase buffers.
No, problem, Data.
I'll be right with you.
Okay, Hansen, transfer
the EPS conduit 13
to the stabilizer matrix.
HANSEN:
Aye, sir.
Is there a problem
with the engines?
No.
Then why are you
stabilizing the
EPS conduit?
Just trying to get
a slightly higher
power conversion level.
But that would not affect
the engines in any way.
I know that, Data.
It's not the point.
What is the point?
I'm just trying to get
a higher conversion
level, that's all.
Why?
You know the Intrepid.
Yes.
Well, their Chief Engineer
is Commander Donald Kaplan.
He and I went through
the Academy together.
I just like to make sure
that our power
conversion levels
are a little bit
higher than theirs.
I understand.
You are in competition
with Mr. Kaplan.
You might say that.
This is the flagship.
We should be better
than everybody else.
Then you are trying
to outperform the Intrepid?
Actually, it's more a
matter of personal pride.
I mean, these
are my engines.
There's nothing wrong
with a little
friendly rivalry.
Okay. Computer
how much have
the conversion
levels increased?
COMPUTER:
Levels are unchanged.
All right, I'll deal
with this later.
Let me give you a hand
with those sensors.
How's that?
One moment.
The phase buffer
is operating
within normal
parameters.
Sensor efficiency has
increased by... 6.7%.
Six point seven?
One of the stages must
still be out of alignment.
Let's try junction A-9.
Geordi, I have taken
your suggestion regarding Spot.
Coming down.
I have begun training her.
Really?
Yes, I am studying
several new techniques.
Huh.
I began with simple
conditioned-response exercises
and followed with
environmental enhancement.
Next, I plan to explore
bioconditioning devices.
Devices?!
Such as sensor nets
for behavior modification
or biofeedback
motivators.
Unfortunately, I have been
less than successful.
I've got an idea.
How about a phaser?
A low stun setting
at just the right moment
might do
the trick.
Geordi, I cannot stun my cat.
I was kidding, Data.
Let's see what we've got.
No, this isn't it,
either.
Clearly, there is
a misalignment
somewhere
in this system.
That's for sure.
Well, we've got
one more possibility.
Junction at C-12?
I am somewhat concerned
that my training efforts
will ultimately fail.
Maybe you're just
going about it
the wrong way, Data.
I have consulted numerous
animal training manuals.
Some of them claim
that cats are
inherently untrainable.
Ah, I don't believe
that for a second.
Listen to me--
my sister didn't know
a thing about animals
and she was able
to train her cat.
How complicated
could it be?
What did she train
her cat to do?
She had that cat jumping
into her arm on command.
Interesting.
Perhaps I could modify
your sister's techniques
to keep Spot from
jumping on the console.
Do you know how
she was able
to train her cat?
Well, as I recall, she walked
around for two months
with a piece of tuna
in her blouse.
Hmm.
I was right.
This buffer is
out of alignment.
Okay, try that.
Phase alignment
is stabilized.
However, sensor efficiency
has increased by only
an additional 1.3%.
Well, it's not much
but every little
bit's going to help.
Riker to Data.
Data here.
We're picking up a ship ahead
on long-range sensors.
If you and Geordi
are through down there
we'd like to have you
on the Bridge.
We're not going
to squeeze
anything else out
of these systems.
Acknowledged, sir.
We are on our way.
We are within
visual range, sir.
On screen.
WORF:
It is a Ferengi transport ship.
D'kora-class.
RIKER:
That's the same Ferengi vessel
that entered the corridor
a week ago.
LA FORGE:
Captain, there are no emissions
from their plasma vents.
Their warp drive
must be completely inactive.
That is correct, sir.
Their impulse system
is down as well.
Power generation
is at extremely low levels.
What about life signs?
Life-support systems are also
functioning at low levels.
There are approximately
450 Ferengi on board.
That is a standard complement
for a ship of that class.
Mr. Worf,
open a hailing frequency.
There is no response
on any channel, sir.
LA FORGE:
I'm not picking up
any subspace emissions
from the ship at all, Captain.
Looks like every one of their
field coils has been overloaded.
That would explain why they
haven't responded to our hails.
DATA:
It would
also explain
the failure of their warp drive.
Captain, the Ferengi sensors
are still on line.
I could modify one
of our deflector emitters
to transmit
old-style delta waves.
If I modulate that
with a com signal
the Ferengi should be able
to pick that up.
Make it so.
If they did hijack
the Fleming
they sure didn't get
very far with the cargo.
Mr. Worf, have tractor
beams standing by.
We may have to take
them under tow.
Helm, take us
within tractor range.
Aye, sir.
Captain I am picking up
power emissions
from the Ferengi vessel.
They are locking weapons.
Shields up!
RIKER:
Ready phasers.
Prepare to return fire.
PICARD:
Target their weapons array only.
Phasers locked.
Fire!
Direct hit--
their weapon systems are down.
Damage report.
We sustained minimal damage
to decks five and seven, sir.
Captain, the Ferengi ship's
power has stabilized.
They appear to have
impulse capability.
They were just
playing dead--
conserving power until
we got in close enough.
And why would
they attack us
in the first place?
Somehow, I don't think
they'll let us beam
over there and ask them.
Mr. La Forge,
how are you coming
with that
com link?
Almost ready, Captain.
All right, let's give it a try.
PICARD:
Open a channel.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
Will you please explain
why you attacked us?
Our attack?
We were defending ourselves.
Do you deny
that you are responsible
for disabling my vessel?
Daimon, your ship was adrift,
your communications inoperable.
We were attempting
to assess your status.
You were attempting to move in
for the kill.
Do not toy with me, Picard.
We are obviously at your mercy,
but know this:
when the Ferengi Council
learns of your actions
they will consider this
an act of war.
Daimon, clearly, there has been
some misunderstanding.
I think it would be
in all our interests
if you were to come aboard
and we discussed this situation.
I see no reason
to trust you, human.
In that case,
we'll be on our way.
I will relay your position
to your government, if you wish
in case you're unable
to complete your repairs
and you remain stranded.
Perhaps, uh...
it would be better
to discuss the situation.
We detected what
appeared to be
a Federation
signal buoy.
When we approached it
it emitted
a massive verteron pulse.
Our warp drive,
our sensors
our communications systems
were all disabled.
We assume we were the victims
of a new Federation weapon.
PICARD:
The Federation
established this corridor
to ensure a safe access
through this sector.
We have nothing to gain
by mining it.
Whatever happened to your ship
may not have been
an isolated incident.
A Federation medical transport
was recently lost
in that corridor.
We passed a Federation ship
several days ago.
It did not appear
to be in any distress.
Can you give us an idea
of its heading?
It is possible
that information was recorded
in our sensor logs, Commander.
Unfortunately, my entire crew
is occupied with our repairs!
I don't think there will be time
to search our records.
Daimon, if we assigned
an engineering team
to assist you
with your repair efforts
would that give you time
to retrieve your logs?
I believe it would, Captain.
Spot?
Spot.
Spot... down.
Down...
( meows )
( sighs )
Spot...
down.
This is down.
Down is good.
This is up.
Up is no.
( door chimes )
One moment.
Come in.
LA FORGE:
Data.
I had another idea
that might help
boost the power
conversion levels.
Can you give me a hand?
I would be happy to.
Don't tell me you're
trying to teach the cat
to use the console.
It is part
of her training program.
I am teaching Spot to jump down
from the desk on my command.
How's it going?
I have not been
entirely successful.
( chuckles )
( Spot meowing )
Feline supplement number 221.
( meows )
Data...
that cat definitely
has a mind of her own.
Maybe she's just not trainable.
I suppose I must accept
that possibility.
It may be that Spot lacks
the intelligence necessary
to learn the appropriate
responses to my commands.
( Spot meowing )
Hmm?
( meows )
Hmm.
I don't know
about Spot
but, seems to me, your training
is coming along just fine.
Come on,
let's go.
Data, keep the EPS
constant, will you
while I remodulate
the power taps?
This procedure
will only increase
the conversion level
by 0.8%.
I know, but it could
be just enough.
Enough?
I just received this from
Commander Kaplan, subspace.
"La Forge, I got
"the Intrepid's power
conversion levels up to 97.1%.
"Maybe you should
try cleaning
your plasma grid
once in a while."
Can you believe
the nerve of that guy?
We perform maintenance
on the plasma grid
at regular intervals.
I know.
He's just trying
to get me angry.
There.
That should do it.
Computer,
what are the current
power conversion levels?
Power conversion levels
are at 97.2%.
Too bad, Mr. Kaplan.
( chuckles )
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have traced the Fleming's
most likely course.
It now appears that the vessel
may have come
to an unfortunate end.
What's the origin
of this debris field?
Unknown, sir.
It does not appear
in any of the Federation charts
of the corridor.
Could it be what's left
of the Fleming?
It is a possibility.
The debris
consists primarily
of duranium and
polycomposite fragments
which suggest a ship.
Furthermore, the field
contains sufficient mass
to account for
the Fleming.
All right.
Let's take
a closer look.
Maybe we can find
something that
will give us
a more positive
identification.
Helm, take us through
the debris field.
Ahead slow.
Captain, I am picking up
a small, metallic object
approximately 3.5 meters
in diameter.
Could be a ship's log recorder,
or a probe casing.
I do not believe so.
It is emitting
an unusual signal.
Captain
it is beginning to generate
a verteron field.
Shields up!
Full reverse! Now!
Damage report.
Warp engines are off-line.
Shields are down.
All subspace systems
are inoperative.
Just like the Ferengi vessel.
Unidentified ship
heading toward us--
two life-forms are aboard.
On screen.
Captain, they are initiating
their transporter system.
Can we get more power
to the shields?
No, sir.
All decks, security alert!
Captain, we are being boarded.
La Forge to Bridge.
We have intruders
in Main Engineering.
I need a security team
down here immediately.
WORF:
It's on its way.
What do you want?
We're trying
to make you listen.
You're killing us.
You have made a very
serious accusation.
I want you to explain it.
Captain, according
to our research
warp fields cause
a dangerous reaction
in this region of space.
Our planet is
already being affected.
We have measured large
gravitational shifts
throughout our system.
If something isn't done
our planet will
become uninhabitable.
Captain, I've heard
this theory before.
Their research was evaluated by
the Federation Science Council
a few years ago.
Quite frankly,
it didn't hold up.
That research was
only preliminary.
Our original analysis
was incomplete.
If you wanted us
to review your research
you should have made a request
through the Science Council.
Their resources are limited.
It would have taken over a year
before they dispatched
a science ship
to come and evaluate our work.
We were not willing to wait
any longer.
We knew that
if we disabled enough ships
Starfleet would come.
Then, at least, we would be able
to present our case.
That's how you rationalize
these attacks?
Neither you nor the Ferengi
suffered any casualties,
Commander.
The actual damage
to your vessels was negligible.
We dispersed verteron probes
in the corridor
merely to disable warp-driven
ships-- nothing more.
You can call it whatever you
like, the fact remains
you deliberately disguised
your probes.
You made them
look like signal markers.
You hid them
in the debris field.
You mined
the corridor!
Mr. La Forge,
how long do you estimate
it will take
to restore the engines?
Their verteron pulse overloaded
our field coils, Captain.
It'll take at least 36 hours
to get underway.
I know precisely how our pulse
affected your field coils.
With my help, your ship could be
operational in ten hours--
provided you agree
to review our research.
Because of the seriousness
of your claim
I am willing
to listen to your case.
But let there be no mistake--
our priority here is
the recovery of the Fleming.
Now, I expect you to help us
restore our engines
and deactivate all
of the remaining probes
in the corridor.
If you do not, you will both
be taken to the brig
and from there
to the nearest Starbase
where you will answer charges
for what you have done.
My sister and I do not wish
to impede your rescue process.
Rabal, don't.
The probes are the only
leverage we have.
Serova.
We will do as you ask, Captain,
but please, reexamine our data.
We will.
It is part of our job
to retain an open mind
even under these circumstances.
Mr. La Forge, take them
to Engineering.
Get the core
back on line.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Data, I want you
to review their research.
I'd like your report
as soon
as possible.
There.
Shields have been restored.
You will be able
to reengage your engines
in approximately
eight hours.
You know, even when we get
the engines on line
it's going to take
at least a week
to recalibrate them properly.
I'm sorry you've been
inconvenienced
but that's all it is--
an inconvenience.
Our concerns are
much more important
than the condition
of your engines.
What if the Fleming
had been transporting
perishable supplies
or was on an emergency mission?
Your little plan might
have cost a lot of lives.
That didn't happen,
Commander.
And saving lives
is precisely what
we're trying to do.
Yeah, well, you have
a very interesting way
of going about it.
There's no point
in trying to talk to you.
You've already decided
not to listen.
RABAL:
Commander
I know my sister
can be somewhat, uh...
aggravating.
I'd have to agree
with that.
But, please, try
to understand--
she believes profoundly
in this cause.
She has sworn
to dedicate her life
to exposing the dangers
of warp drive.
Warp drive has been around
for three centuries.
It's a proven
technology.
And you sound just like I did--
about four years ago.
You mean, you didn't
believe her either?
No. What I didn't realize was
just how brilliant my sister is.
It took two years
of study for me
to even grasp the principles
behind her theoretical models.
They're that sophisticated.
Well, our Commander Data
is no slouch.
If there's anything there,
he'll find it.
Well, I hope so.
Because once we
persuade Starfleet
to stop warp travel
through the corridor
we're going to have
to convince our own people
to give up warp drive
completely.
Hekaras II is the only
inhabited world in this region.
Without warp drive,
you'd be completely isolated
from the rest of the Federation.
Are you really willing
to take that step?
Yes, and if you were
in my position
I hope you'd be willing
to do the same thing.
Serova and Rabal believe
that there are regions
of potential subspace
instability within the corridor.
They believe
that if these regions
continue to be exposed
to warp field energy
they will rupture.
Subspace will extrude into
normal space, forming a rift.
It's like pacing up and down
on the same piece of carpet--
eventually you wear it out.
That analogy
is essentially correct, sir.
Can this theory be proven?
Not at this
time, sir.
There is
insufficient
evidence to do so.
In order to determine
whether or not a rift will form
a region must be exposed
to warp field energy
approximately
one million times greater
than that normally generated
by a starship.
Commander, we believe
the warp field effect
is cumulative.
Each starship that passes
through the corridor at warp
brings us one step closer
to forming
a rift.
I agree that is a possibility.
Captain,
I suggest we ask
the Federation Science Council
to send a research
vessel to this area.
A more detailed
investigation
would resolve
many of our questions.
That's your response--
more research, more delays.
I suppose I shouldn't have
expected anything different.
RIKER:
Bridge to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Number One.
We've located the Fleming
on long-range sensors--
approximately
0.3 light years away.
What's her condition?
The vessel appears to be intact.
They have shields,
but it looks
like their subspace
systems are out.
Very well.
We'll be under way
as soon as our engines
are on line.
Aye, sir.
I would like you all
to put together
a research proposal
for the Science Council.
I will give it
my full recommendation.
Captain, I appreciate the
opportunity you're giving us.
It's a beginning
that we...
Not "we."
You can do whatever
you want, Rabal.
I'll have no part of this.
It's just another delay.
( sighs )
Captain, the engines
are back on line.
All systems are ready.
Very good.
Helm, lay in a course
for the Fleming.
Aye, sir.
They appear to be
in pretty good condition.
Our sensors show their shields
are back to full strength.
WORF:
Captain, the Hekaran ship
is moving off.
There is one person on board.
It is Serova.
Doctor, what is going on?
I don't know.
Captain, may I speak to her?
Mr. Worf, open a channel.
RABAL:
Serova, what are
you trying to do?
They wanted proof.
I'm going to give it to them.
I'm sorry.
Captain,
the Hekaran ship's engines
are beginning to overload.
I believe Serova
is attempting to create
a warp core breach.
No.
RIKER:
Prepare for impact.
Shields at maximum.
Full reverse.
Report.
DATA:
We are clear
of the shock wave.
However, tetryon flux in
the area is increasing rapidly.
It's incredible.
Mr. Data
what's your analysis?
The event is approximately
0.1 light years in diameter
and it is emitting
extremely high levels
of tetryon radiation.
It appears to be
what Rabal and
Serova predicted--
a subspace rift.
She was right.
Can you get a fix
on the Fleming?
Is she still in one piece?
Scanning.
The Fleming is near
its previous coordinates.
It appears to be intact,
but it is now within the rift.
Doctor, is it possible
for a ship to survive in there?
Doctor, I'm sorry about your
loss, but we need your help now.
Of course, Captain.
Does the rift pose any danger
to the Fleming?
I don't know.
What was that?
Some kind of high-energy
distortion wave.
Looks like they're being
generated from within the rift.
If we maintain
our current position
our shields should provide
sufficient protection.
What about the Fleming?
How long can they
survive in there?
The waves are even more intense
within the rift.
I estimate her shields will fail
in approximately
12 hours.
Can we risk going in there
to get them out?
LA FORGE:
Not at warp, Commander.
According to these readings
the rift is in a state
of accelerating instability
which would make it
extremely sensitive
to warp field energies.
If we go in at warp
we might expand it even further.
I don't think
we have a choice.
It would take weeks
to reach them at impulse.
I want some better options.
Data, Geordi, take Dr. Rabal
and begin an analysis
of the rift.
We need to find some way to get
the Fleming out of there.
DATA:
Second Officer's Log,
Stardate 47312.1.
Our new sensor readings
have greatly improved
our understanding of the rift.
However, we have been
unable to find
any way to counteract it.
LA FORGE:
Everything here supports
Serova's theories.
I can't find any way
to close the rift
or even reduce its size.
Doctor, is it possible
there are areas inside
the rift which are stable
where we can safely
use our warp engines?
Perhaps.
Computer, scan
the rift
for regions of
low instability.
There's no area
stable enough
to withstand a warp pulse.
Wait a minute.
This is strange.
Computer, display grid Delta-17.
Enhance and magnify.
What do you make of that?
It's a subspace instability--
outside the rift.
That should not be possible.
Commander, I'm going to begin
a field-enhanced scan
of this sector.
I'd like to get
a closer look at this.
In the meantime, we'd
better tell the Captain
we don't know how to get
to the Fleming.
I am not certain
that is true.
I believe
I have an idea.
I suggest
we coast into the rift.
Coast?
We can initiate a brief,
high-intensity warp pulse
from our current position.
We should be able to attain
sufficient velocity
to enter the rift
beam the crew
off the Fleming
and exit without using
our warp engines.
All right, let's say we initiate
a full-power warp pulse.
How much time do we need
to drop out of warp?
If we field-saturate
the nacelles
we should be able
to sustain warp speed
for approximately two minutes.
That doesn't give us much time.
And it could get
pretty rough in there.
Our timing will be critical.
Begin your calculations,
Mr. Data.
We'll go as soon
as you're ready.
Aye, sir.
( sighs )
I believe the maximum saturation
level should be 18.3%.
All right.
With these parameters
we should be able
to maintain warp speed
for... two minutes,
eight seconds.
I don't think we can get
any more than that.
I agree, but based on
the size of the rift
it should give us sufficient
time to complete the rescue.
Computer, initiate
nacelle field saturation.
How did we
miss it, Data?
Beg your pardon.
How did we miss
the connection
between warp drive
and the formation of the rift?
Between the two of us
we've logged thousands of hours
on these engines.
We're supposed
to be warp field experts.
We certainly were wrong
this time.
Technically, Geordi,
we were not wrong.
Serova's theories
rested on assumptions
which were unprovable.
Seems to me she managed
to prove them
pretty conclusively.
By using methods
any reputable scientist
would never employ.
Yeah, she was willing to die
in order to make her point.
We should have listened to her
more closely, Data.
We reviewed Serova's research
to the best of our abilities
and we were prepared to continue
studying the problem
but that was unsatisfactory.
Yeah, I can remember times
when I was a little stubborn.
Trying to get people
to believe me
when I didn't have
enough proof.
I do not believe you would have
resorted to such extremes.
But she had to--
just to get us to listen.
Why was I so resistant?
Perhaps because
her aggressive methods
created
an adversarial situation.
Yeah.
Maybe I was taking
the whole thing personally.
I do not understand.
( sighs )
Maybe... I was
a little threatened.
The thought that warp engines
might be doing
some kind of damage.
It's going to take
another half an hour
for the nacelles
to saturate.
Will you call me
when they're done?
Commander.
May I join you?
I wanted to say I'm sorry
about your sister.
Thank you.
I'm trying to tell myself
that she died
for what she believed in
but, somehow,
that isn't much comfort.
I wish it could have happened
differently.
Maybe I should have looked
at the research more closely.
It's possible there's something
that I missed.
No, you didn't miss anything.
The problem was time.
We needed more time
to do the proper research.
Serova wasn't willing to wait.
No. I guess the question is,
now, where do we go from here?
I don't think we can look
at space travel
the same way anymore.
We're going to have to change.
I've been in Starfleet
a long time.
We depend on warp drive.
I just don't know how easy
it's going to be to change.
It won't be easy at all.
Captain, warp pulse
calculations are complete.
We will be firing the engines
at maximum intensity
for 6.3 seconds
before disengaging.
WORF:
Damage control teams
are standing by on all decks.
The course to the Fleming
is plotted and laid in, sir.
Mr. La Forge,
whenever you're ready.
Aye, sir.
Initiating warp pulse... now.
Engines disengaged.
We are now
entering the rift.
Hull stress
is increasing--
83% of maximum tolerance
and rising.
How long until
we reach the Fleming?
One minute, 22 seconds.
All transporter rooms
are standing by.
Captain, I'm picking up power
emissions from the Fleming.
They may be attempting
to initiate
their warp drive.
They might have been able
to repair their engines.
Captain, if
they activate...
I know, Mr. Data.
Can we establish
communication?
WORF:
No, sir-- subspace interference
is too high.
How long until we reach
transporter range?
WORF:
53 seconds.
I don't think
we're going to make it.
Captain, they have initiated
their warp drive.
Report.
WORF:
Damage on decks six and 14.
Our structural integrity field
is holding.
What about
the Fleming?
They are badly
damaged, sir.
Their life-support
systems are failing.
All transporter rooms
prepare emergency
evacuation procedures.
Captain, when the Fleming
activated their warp drive
the rift increased by 2.3%.
We no longer have
sufficient momentum to escape.
Distortion wave intensity has
increased by a factor of ten.
We are within transporter range
of the Fleming, sir.
Commencing
evacuation procedures.
Distortion waves occurring
every 59 seconds.
Hull stress is nearing
maximum tolerance.
Data, what if we forced
an EPS discharge
through the impulse reactor?
Would that be enough
to get us out of here?
I do not believe so, sir
and the resulting explosion
would likely destroy
the saucer section
in the process.
Captain, we may be able
to get out of here
without using the warp engines.
RIKER:
How, Geordi?
When was the last time
you went surfing, Commander?
A distortion wave?
Exactly, Captain.
If we can phase-match
our deflector shield
to the EM variants
of the distortion wave
when the next one hits
we'll be pulled along
with it.
We could ride it
through the rift
and then break away
once we're clear--
that is, if we
survive the ride.
Is everyone
off the Fleming?
The last of the crew
has beamed aboard, sir.
All right, Mr. La Forge.
Get us out of here.
Yes, sir.
Phase-matching
the deflector shields now.
The next distortion wave
will impact in 14 seconds.
Matching phases...
Prepare to engage
the deflector shield on my mark.
DATA:
Ten seconds.
And... mark!
Engage deflector shield,
full power.
We lost it.
We were unable to maintain
phase match
with the distortion wave, sir.
What went wrong,
Mr. La Forge?
The speed differential
was too high, Captain.
Another distortion wave
approaching.
Impact in 26 seconds.
Our hull stress is
already critical.
We can't handle
many more jolts like that.
Captain, I suggest we take
the ship to full impulse.
If we can attain
sufficient speed
it will lessen the impact
when the wave hits.
Helm, full impulse.
Head us out of the rift.
Mr. Worf, channel
all available power
to the structural
integrity fields.
Aye, sir.
Stand by,
deflector shields.
We're ready, Captain.
Distortion wave impact
in five seconds.
Engage deflector shield... now!
We are now
within the distortion wave.
Hull stresses have
exceeded maximum tolerance.
Structural integrity fields
are failing on decks ten
through 16.
Switching to backups.
We're separating
from the distortion wave.
I'm attempting to compensate.
How much longer until
we clear the rift?
DATA:
Approximately
12 seconds, sir.
Hull stress
is 120% above tolerance.
A structural breach is imminent.
We have cleared
the rift, sir.
Hull stress has
returned to normal.
Cancel red alert.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47314.5.
We have been continuing
our research
while the Federation Council
studies our preliminary reports
on the subspace rift.
It now appears certain
that what we've seen here
will have repercussions
for many years to come.
Our scans show a lot
of subspace instabilities
throughout the sector.
If they're exposed
to enough warp energies
they could eventually
create other rifts.
Dr. Rabal?
Based on current
warp drive patterns
in this sector, we've projected
where subspace rifts
will be most likely to be formed
over the next 40 years.
This is how things are now.
This is how they'll look
in ten years...
20 years...
30 years...
40 years.
Thank you, Doctor.
Mr. La Forge.
Ah...
We've received new directives
from the Federation Council
on this matter.
Until we can find a way
to counteract
the warp field effect
the Council feels
our best course
is to slow the damage
as much as possible.
Therefore, areas of space
found susceptible to warp fields
will be restricted
to essential travel only
and, effective immediately,
all Federation vessels
will be limited to a speed...
of warp five
except in cases
of extreme emergency.
Well, the Klingons will
observe these restrictions
but the Romulans will not.
And what about the Ferengi
and the Cardassians,
for that matter?
The Federation
is sharing all our data
with warp-capable species.
We can only hope
that they realize
it's in their own interests
and take similar action.
Putting limits on warp speed
is only going to prevent
other rifts from forming.
What are we going
to do about this one?
Unfortunately, right now,
there's not much we can do.
RABAL:
The gravitational shifts
have already begun
to affect my planet's orbit.
Our climate is changing.
The Federation is setting up
a weather control matrix
on Hekaras II.
It's only a temporary solution,
but it should suffice for now.
We're lucky the rift took place
as far away
from the planet as it did.
It gives us some time
to consider our options.
If there are no more questions,
you're all dismissed.
We should have those
thermal stabilizers ready
for the Hekarans
in another day, sir.
Very well.
You know, Geordi
I've spent the better part of
my life exploring space.
I've charted new worlds, I've
met dozens of new species
and I believe that these were
all valuable ends in themselves.
And now it seems that...
all this while
I was... helping to damage
the thing
that I hold most dear.
It won't turn out
that way, Captain.
We still have time
to make it better.