Captain's Log,
Stardate 47410.2.
The Atrean government
has requested assistance
in averting a natural disaster.
Two of their geologists
have come aboard
one of whom is a human who
has been living on Atrea IV.
Captain, the situation
has worsened
since my husband and I
first contacted you.
The molten core of our
planet isn't just cooling--
it's begun to solidify.
MAN:
Our gravitational field
has been affected.
Seismic activity has increased
by a factor of three.
If the cooling
continues at this rate
Atrea will become
uninhabitable
in 13 months.
LA FORGE:
We could minimize
seismic activity by creating
isobaric fissures and relieving
some of the tectonic stress
but that would just
be a temporary fix.
The only
permanent solution
would be to reliquefy
the core.
These pockets
in the magma layer--
how close are they
to the molten region
of the core?
A few kilometers.
Why?
Data, you think
that's close enough
for ferroplasmic infusion?
The procedure will involve
using the ship's phasers
to drill down through
the planet's surface
into the pockets,
where we would set up
a series of plasma
infusion units.
We'll trigger the units
by firing modulated
energy bursts
down through the shafts.
I see.
Injecting plasma
directly into the core
should trigger
a chain reaction
and that will reliquefy
the magma.
It should be possible
to stabilize
the core temperature
at 93% of normal.
If it works
the core would remain
molten for centuries.
If you'll give your permission,
we could begin immediately.
Very well.
But before we proceed
I'd like to update
our geological surveys.
Fine. I'd be very happy to
help you with that, Doctor.
We've assigned you quarters
during our time here.
Please make yourselves
comfortable.
Thank you, Captain.
Data?
Yes, Doctor.
Do you have
any idea who I am?
You are
Dr. Juliana Tainer.
Oh, you lost all your
early memories.
We thought you would,
but we couldn't be certain.
Have we met before?
Oh, Data,
I was there
right at the beginning
on Omicron Theta.
I helped create you.
And now...
look at you.
You were a colleague
of Dr. Soong?
I most certainly was...
and I was
also his wife.
In a way, I suppose
you could say
I am your mother.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
... to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
... to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I just can't believe
I'm seeing you
like this again
after all these years.
Doctor, I have
no memory of you.
Oh, there's
a reason for that.
We wiped your
processors
after we finished
refining your programming.
Why don't you tell me
what you do remember
and then
I'll fill in the gaps.
My memory record begins
when I was activated
by the Starfleet officers
on the Omicron
Theta outpost.
Ah, after the attack
of the Crystalline Entity.
Yes. All of the inhabitants
of the colony were killed.
However, I discovered
that my memory banks
contain the contents
of their journals and logs.
We hoped their experiences
would be useful.
After your childhood
we figured you could use
all the help you could get.
"My childhood?"
Oh, well, that's
what I called it.
Well, you were like
a baby, at first...
a 100-kilogram baby,
but still.
You had trouble, uh,
learning
your motor skills
learning how to process
sensory information
and, of course, Noonien
was never satisfied.
He kept tinkering
trying to make you
as human as possible.
So you wiped
my memory processors
after this "childhood"?
Mm-hmm.
Then we deactivated you
and programmed you
with the colonists' logs.
We had planned to
reactivate you
but we never
got the chance.
That's when the Crystalline
Entity attacked.
We had to
leave quickly.
We wanted to take you
with us
but there was only room
for two in the escape pod.
Doctor, I have scanned
the journals
of the colonists.
There is only one Juliana
mentioned in them.
Her last name
was O'Donnell.
That's me.
But there was no mention that
my father was married to you.
Because of my mother.
She thought that Noonien
was an eccentric scientist
who was far too
old for me.
We decided to marry secretly
to give her a chance to get
used to our being together.
We slipped away to Mavala IV
and got married there.
A Klingon and a Corvallen
trader were our witnesses.
It wasn't exactly the wedding
I'd hoped for, but...
( chuckles )
somehow, Noonien had a way
of making even the oddest
things seem romantic.
My father did have an unusual
way of looking at things.
How would you know that?
I encountered him once
in the Terlina system.
Why, that's where we went to,
after we left the outpost.
I'd no idea
that you'd even met him.
It was shortly
before his death.
He's dead?
Yes.
( sighs )
I had no idea
it would hit me this hard.
We didn't exactly part
on the best of terms.
What do you mean?
Oh, I realized
he loved his work
as much as he
loved me...
maybe more.
Oh, there we were
stuck out on this planet
in the middle of
the jungle
with no one else
to talk to...
no... life.
It just wasn't enough.
That's why I left.
But that was all a very,
very long time ago.
The important thing is
that we're here now, together
and I do want to get
to know you.
This has been
an interesting encounter
and an altogether
unexpected one.
I would like
to corroborate
your story before
we proceed further.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Data, I'm almost
finished
reconfiguring
the phaser banks.
We should be able to start
drilling in about an hour.
Inform me
when you are ready.
What is it you're
doing over there?
I am attempting
to ascertain
whether Dr. Tainer's
story is true.
Don't you
believe her?
I neither believe
nor doubt.
I am simply trying
to verify her assertions.
Well, what have you
turned up so far?
The registrar's office
on Mavala IV
cannot confirm whether
Dr. Soong was married there.
Apparently, many of
the documents were lost
when the government
was overthrown.
What's that
you're looking at?
I am checking
passenger manifests
to see if they went to
Mavala IV
during
the period in question.
"O'Donnell, Juliana."
"Soong, Noonien."
They were both passengers
on a transport which traveled
from Omicron Theta to Mavala
and returned
four days later.
That sure fits
with her story.
Still, the fact that
they went to Mavala
does not prove
they were married there.
You know, Data,
it almost seems to me
like you're trying
to prove
that Dr. Tainer
wasn't telling the truth.
Not at all.
I am merely unable
to reconcile her story
with the fact that my father
never mentioned her to me.
Well, she did leave him.
Maybe she broke
his heart.
Maybe he just didn't
want to talk about her.
Let me ask you this.
Dr. Soong created
an emotion chip for you
and didn't Lore tell you
that that chip also
contained memories--
memories Soong
wanted you to have?
Yes.
It is possible that those
are memories of my childhood
and of Mrs. Soong.
And when you think about it,
why would she want to lie?
Why would anybody want to
pretend to be your mother?
I can think of no motive
for such a pretense.
You know, I can understand
that this might
all be a little
disconcerting
for you, Data.
It came
out of the blue
and it doesn't fit
into your
logical processors.
That is true.
But that's life, Data.
Part of being human
is learning how to deal
with the unexpected.
To risk new experiences
even when they don't fit
into your preconceptions.
I admit
I am finding it difficult
to accept the possibility
of a past
about which
I know nothing.
But it is also true
I am curious
to learn more about it.
Data?
I would like to get
to know you better...
Mother.
I wanted to make
you female
but your father
insisted on a son.
Oh, we argued
about it endlessly
right up until we were
ready to assemble you.
How did you decide?
Oh, Noonien walked in
with your head in his hand
and, innocent as you please,
said it was up to me.
Well, he knew perfectly
well what he was doing.
Once again, he had made it
in his own image.
I mean, what
could I possibly say?
Deanna Troi?
Is that who you're
going to visit?
Yes.
Oh, your father
would be so pleased.
Pleased?
Well, he was worried
that the sexuality program
he designed for you
wouldn't work.
You misunderstand.
Counselor Troi
is a therapist.
Good night.
We will be in position
over the drilling site
in three minutes,
29 seconds.
These scans indicate
that the magma pockets
where we planned to set up
the infusion units
are somewhat unstable.
Well, I'm going to monitor
the density of
the rock layers
and adjust the strength of
the particle beam as we go.
That should minimize
the seismic stress
that we'll generate
while we're drilling.
Data, I reconfigured
the phasers
to create the most
highly focused
particle beam possible.
Thank you, Geordi.
( chuckling )
I'm just so pleased
you've got good manners.
It wasn't easy to strike
the right balance
with your
programming.
Well, at first, you
couldn't have cared less
about the social niceties
like "please"
and "thank you."
You were downright
rude, in fact.
Data?
Well, that's hard
to picture.
Well, that was nothing
to the problems
we encountered...
Never mind.
I don't want
to embarrass you.
I am incapable
of embarrassment.
Please continue.
Well, the one thing
that we couldn't anticipate
was that you didn't seem
to mind about being
uh... naked.
Some of the colonists
objected to having
an anatomically correct
android running around
without any
clothes on.
Oh, we asked you to dress
but you didn't feel
it was necessary
because you didn't
suffer from the elements.
We actually had to write
a modesty subroutine
to get you to
keep your clothes on.
Riker to engineering.
La Forge here.
Go ahead, Commander.
We've established synchronous
orbit over the drilling site.
Phaser modifications
are on line, sir.
My calculations
indicate
that the first phaser blast
will be approximately
19 seconds in duration.
Acknowledged.
Someone's checked his
calculations, of course.
No, but I'm sure Mr. Data
knows what he's doing.
Even so, he is
a machine.
Someone should
check up on him.
I have complete confidence
in Mr. Data's ability
to check up on himself.
Mr. Worf?
Phasers locked
on target.
Fire when ready.
We are within two kilometers
of the magma pocket.
Another five seconds
should do it.
We've broken through.
Terminating the beam.
Oh, the pocket
seems stable.
I detect no increase
in the stress levels
of the surrounding magma.
RIKER:
Good work, Data.
I don't think we could
have gotten in any cleaner.
JULIANA:
We have Data to
thank for that.
I couldn't have done it
without him.
His figures
were perfect.
The drilling process
has increased the temperature
in the magma pockets
by almost
300 degrees Celsius.
It will be several hours
before it cools enough
for us to enter.
( sigh of relief )
Data, do you have
any plans right now?
I do not.
Maybe we should spend
a little time together.
I'd love to see
your quarters.
( classical violin
music playing )
Thank you.
I will be playing this piece
at a recital tomorrow evening.
That was beautiful.
Hmm.
I have been told
that my playing
is technically flawless
but no one has ever described
it as beautiful.
It was. Really.
Are you certain
you are not saying this
because you are
my mother?
( laughing )
I have noticed that parents
tend to exaggerate
when it comes to their
children's accomplishments.
Oh, I suppose
there's a certain amount
of vanity involved
considering that giving you
a creative aspect was my idea.
Oh, your father didn't
really see the point.
He thought that since
you didn't have emotions
there would be no real need
for you to express yourself.
Somehow, I had the feeling
that the opposite
would be true.
I do not know for certain,
but I believe it is during
my creative endeavors
that I come closest
to experiencing
what it must be
like to be human.
Well, I'm glad
I insisted.
As am I.
Data...
I'm very familiar
with that Handel piece.
How would you feel about
my playing
the viola part tomorrow?
I would like
that very much.
Well, I'll have to
practice.
You don't happen
to have a viola?
I could replicate
one for you.
Computer, please
replicate one viola.
Did you paint these?
Yes.
I am attempting
to master
all known
styles of painting.
Oh!
This one is
in the style
of the early French
Impressionists.
Oh, it's very good.
Who's this?
That is Lal,
my daughter.
Your daughter?
I created her
using myself as a model.
Where is she now?
The positronic matrix
I designed for her
was unstable.
She only lived
a short time.
I see.
In a sense, you were
her grandmother.
Would you like
to practice now?
Yes. Yes, of course.
( playing classical music )
The acoustics in Ten-Forward
are most favorable.
Yes. Yes, very nice.
Data, may I ask
you something?
Of course.
Do you think
you'll ever try to create
an android again?
Perhaps.
I created Lal because
I wished to procreate.
Despite what happened to her,
I still have that wish.
But how do you know
the same thing won't happen?
Creating a stable positron
matrix is very tricky.
Your father lost
several prototypes
before Lore.
I was not aware
he created other
androids before
my brother.
There were
three of them.
They were like
children to us.
Losing them
was very painful.
When Noonien decided
to try again
I was very
much against it.
I didn't think we had
the right to bring a life
into the world
with so little
chance of surviving.
But your father was sure
that he'd figured out
what went wrong.
He insisted he could make
a stable matrix, and he did.
But Lore was...
cruel...
evil.
Eventually,
we had no choice.
We had to dismantle him.
Your father decided to build
yet another android--
one who
didn't have emotions.
I couldn't believe...
he would
want to try again.
I am that android.
Are you saying you were
against my creation?
Initially I was,
but I was wrong.
I know that now.
I followed your
progress for years.
I'm very proud of what
you've accomplished.
Then, why did you never
attempt to contact me?
Because I felt guilty
about something I'd done.
Perhaps if you told me what
has made you feel this way
it would
alleviate the guilt.
I lied...
when I said there
was no room for you
in the escape pod
we took from Omicron.
( voice breaking ):
There was.
I didn't want to
bring you with us.
I was afraid
if we reactivated you
you'd turn out like Lore.
I made Noonien
leave you behind.
We are within
four kilometers
of the magma pocket.
We're picking up feedback pulses
along the particle beam.
We must have hit
a pocket of magnesite ore.
I'll try to adjust the phaser
harmonics to compensate.
RIKER:
Data, we're going to have
to terminate the beam
if this keeps up.
If we do, we will have
to begin a new shaft
at a suitable location.
There is no other
suitable location.
Just give me
a few more seconds.
Doctor, it's going to take
longer than that to match the...
You did it.
It was just luck
I hit the right frequency.
All right, we're less
than two kilometers away
from the target site.
Stand by to
terminate the beam.
We've broken through.
Now!
I am detecting no signs
of instability.
Commander, may I suggest
we set up the infusion unit
in the first magma pocket
and give this one
a chance to cool?
Data, Dr. Tainer
we'll meet you
in transporter room two.
Acknowledged.
I have initialized
the plasma induction coils.
I'll need another minute
to align the diverter.
There are signs of stress
in the surrounding magma
but the site
should remain stable
until we finish
the plasma infusion.
Good.
We're almost through here.
Data...
Juliana told me what she
said to you last night.
She's been
very upset.
I don't blame you
for being angry with her...
I am incapable
of anger.
It's all right, Pran.
I know what
I said to you
must have been hard
for you to hear
but I hope you
understand my reasons.
I am not certain I do.
Perhaps you could
clarify them for me.
Well, I'll try.
What do you want to know?
If I had been
your biological offspring
would you have left me
on Omicron Theta?
Oh, Data...
how can I answer that?
Dr. Tainer,
I get the impression
you are trying to spare
my feelings.
I assure you
that is not
necessary.
I just don't want you to
misunderstand my answer.
No, I wouldn't have
left you behind
if you'd been
my biological child.
Hmm. Is that because you
place more value
on biological life
than artificial life?
Absolutely not.
I cherished every android
your father and I created
as if it were my child.
Even Lore.
Despite the fact
that he turned on us
despite the dreadful
things he did
dismantling him was
was the most difficult
thing I ever had to do.
I was afraid that if you
turned out like him
I would have
to dismantle you, too.
And I couldn't
bear to do that.
I'm not trying to justify
leaving you behind.
I'm just sorry I did.
I hope you
believe me.
I do.
Thank you for making
it clear to me.
( classical music playing )
Just wonderful.
Bravo.
Data, why do you
want to look at
Dr. Tainer's medical records?
Is something
wrong with her?
I was hoping you would
be able to determine that
from her transporter
trace pattern.
Well, probably
I could
but ordinarily I don't check
somebody's medical status
without a good reason.
Doctor, I would ask
that you not require me
to be more specific.
I assure you
I have a good reason
for asking.
All right, Data.
At first glance,
I see nothing wrong with her
except for a mild case
of hypertension
which is normal
for a woman her age.
I see.
Maybe you should tell me
what her symptoms are.
She has not complained
of any discomfort.
Then why do you want to
see her medical records?
Because I have
reason to believe
she is not who
she claims to be.
RIKER:
Bridge to Data.
Go ahead, sir.
There's been a cave-in
in one of the magma pockets.
You're needed
in transporter room two.
On my way.
Excuse me, Doctor.
What happened?
We were running
a final check
on the infusion units
when a part of
the wall gave way.
It looks like the area
has stabilized
but seismic
stress is building up.
Eventually the pocket
will collapse.
RIKER:
How long, Geordi?
It's tough to tell,
Commander.
12 hours at most.
Then we must finish
configuring the unit
and inject the plasma
immediately.
I'd rather not send
anyone back down there.
If you don't do it
now, Commander
it may take months to
find another suitable site.
The core may
solidify by then.
She's right.
We have to act now.
All right, but I want you
in and out of there
as quickly as possible.
Acknowledged.
You're hurt.
I'll go.
( tricorder beeping )
( rumbling )
( gasps )
There will be more
seismic activity.
We must hurry.
The shaft has not been
obstructed
by seismic activity.
It should be
possible
to trigger
the unit from orbit.
The infuser's been damaged.
We're going to
have to start
the programming sequence
all over again.
Priming the energy
transfer matrix.
Reinitializing
the particle stream buffer.
Riker to Data.
Are you there?
Go ahead, sir.
We're reading an increase
in seismic stress levels.
Understood, sir.
We will attempt to
expedite our work.
There. Now we just have
to realign the diverter.
Data, are you
all right?
Yes, sir.
We will be returning
to the beam-out
point shortly.
That's it. Let's go.
( gasps )
Can we transport without
the pattern enhancers?
No. We are too far
below the surface.
How are we going
to get down there?
There are no handholds
in the rock face.
( gasping cry )
We are going
to have to jump.
No. It's too far,
I won't make it.
You will.
LA FORGE:
Basically, she's
a Soong-type android
except everything about her
is designed to fool you
into thinking she's human.
She has tear ducts,
sweat glands
even veins and capillaries
underneath her skin.
Why does the scanner
read her as human?
Because she has
a feedback processor
designed to send out
a false bio-signal.
It's part of her
aging program.
Not only does she age
in appearance like Data
her vital signs change, too.
What I can't
figure out
is why she lost
consciousness.
As far as I can see,
everything is fine.
She should be awake.
Check her
positronic matrix.
There may be a cascade
anomaly.
You said you knew
she was an android. How?
The first indication occurred
when we were digging.
I saw her perform
complex calculations
without the assistance
of the computer.
That could have just meant
she was good at math.
That is true.
But it was enough
to get my attention.
Later, I noticed
something odd
about the way she
blinked her eyes.
The intervals
between blinks
were governed by
the Fourier system--
the same mathematical
formula my father used
to give my blinking pattern
the appearance of randomness.
Only you could have noticed
something like that.
Then there was the
concert in Ten-Forward.
What about it?
We had practiced the
piece, and I noticed
she played it the same way
during the performance--
every pitch, every intonation
was exactly the same.
Only an artificial life-form
could have done that.
Does her husband
know anything about this?
I do not
believe so.
He is on the surface
monitoring
the plasma infusion.
Probably just as well.
LA FORGE:
Data, come take
a look at this.
It appears to be an
information module.
With a holographic
interface.
( clicking )
Whoever you are
you must have found out
about Juliana.
That is correct.
I programmed this hologram
to answer any questions
you might have.
I am Noonien Soong.
I created her.
I am Data.
Data?
I hoped somehow
it would be you.
I even created
a response program
to answer your questions.
How are you, boy?
I am fine.
I'm glad you got the chance
to meet your mother.
You refer to Dr. Tainer
as my mother
yet the complexity
of her design indicates
she was created after I was.
You're right.
But...
there was a real
Juliana O'Donnell.
She was my wife.
She helped me
create you.
What happened to her?
She was... injured
when the Crystalline
Entity attacked.
We made it as far
as Terlina III
but...
she slipped into
a coma.
When I realized
nothing could be done for her,
I built an android.
I tried to...
perfect my synaptic
scanning technique
so that I could transfer
Juliana's memories
into a positronic matrix.
Didn't know
if it would work
but I had to try.
I couldn't
stand the thought
of losing the only woman
I ever loved.
A few days
after Juliana died,
I activated the android.
She looked up
at me...
and smiled.
She recognized me.
It had worked!
Here was a life
not two minutes old
and as far as she
was concerned,
I was her husband.
She'd just recovered
from a terrible injury.
It was incredible.
Then you never
told her the truth?
Why?
There was no reason
for her to know.
I wanted
her to be happy.
I wanted us to be happy.
And we were...
( sighs )
...for awhile.
What happened?
I made
a terrible mistake.
I never really...
let her know
how much I loved her.
So she left me.
The real Juliana
would have left, too
if she had lived.
If she recovers
and learns that
she is an android...
She doesn't
have to know.
Now, I designed her
to shut down
in the event that
the truth was discovered.
When you... when you
put that chip back in
she will wake up
and remember nothing.
All you have to do is
make up some excuse
about what
happened to her.
Then you do not believe
she should know the truth?
The truth.
The truth is
in every way
that matters
she is Juliana Soong.
I programmed her
to terminate
after a long life.
Let her
live out her days
and die believing
she was human.
Don't rob her
of that, son...
please.
It seems that
I must make a decision--
whether to tell Dr. Tainer
that she is an android
or to withhold that
information from her.
I do not know
what to do.
Why was Dr. Soong so adamant
that she not be told?
He seemed certain
that if she knew
it would preclude the
possibility of her being happy.
Data,
what do you think?
I am not certain.
I understand why my father
felt as he did
but his wishes are not
necessarily paramount.
I am more concerned
with what would
be best for her.
Wouldn't she be
better off knowing the truth
dealing with the reality
of her existence?
I don't think so.
She's believed
she's human all her life.
The truth might be
devastating to her.
Data, there might come
some time in the future
when she would
find out anyway--
another accident,
perhaps.
Maybe it would be
easier for her
if she learned
the truth from you.
I can tell you
that if I were in her place
I would rather be told by my
son than by some stranger.
I find I am having
difficulty separating
what would be best for her
from what
would be best for me.
What do you mean?
If she knew she were
an android
we would have
something to share.
I would no longer be alone
in the universe.
I know how much
that means to you, Data
but at the same time,
by telling her
you're robbing
her of the one thing
you've wanted all
your life--
to be human.
It's a difficult choice.
You must do what
you think best, Data.
But whatever decision
you make,
we will support it.
Data.
What happened?
The last thing I remember
was jumping off a cliff.
You were knocked
unconscious by the fall.
You broke
a bone in your arm
but Dr. Crusher
repaired it.
Everything is fine.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The infusion of plasma
into the core of Atrea IV
has been accomplished.
The core should remain molten
for several hundred years.
When will I
see you again?
Perhaps I can visit
Atrea on my next leave.
I would like
that very much.
Well, I'd better
be going.
There is something
I think you should know.
My father told me...
that he had only one
great love in his life
and that he regretted
never telling her
how much
he cared for her.
I am certain he was
referring to you.
That's nice to know.
On Atrea,
there is a saying
that a child born
from parents who
love each other
will have nothing
but goodness in his heart.
I guess that explains you.
Take care of
yourself, son.
Good-bye... Mother.
Energize.