Personal Log,
Stardate 47391.2.
I am returning from the Bat'leth
competition on Forcas III.
The conditions were
difficult.
Several contestants were maimed,
but I was triumphant.
I won
champion standing.
I am looking forward
to resuming my duties
aboard the Enterprise.
However...
I am anticipating
a troubling situation.
It looks like we're
going to have to head
into the Argus Array.
This is the third time
this year
it's stopped
relaying data.
Starfleet's beginning
to think that it's more
than a simple
malfunction.
I want you to start
a long-range scan once we get...
Lieutenant,
are you listening to me?
Hmm? Yes, sir.
You seem awfully tense
for a man who just
came back
from vacation.
Today is my... birthday.
What's the matter
with you?
Because it is
my birthday,
I assumed that you
or one of the others
would try to mount
an unexpected
social gathering.
A surprise party?
Mr. Worf,
I hate surprise parties.
I would never
do that to you.
I am sorry,
Commander.
Settle in.
I'll meet you on the bridge.
Aye, sir.
ALL:
Surprise!
( noisemakers popping )
I love
surprise parties.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( to the tune of "For He's
a Jolly Good Fellow" )
♪ Cha Worf
toh'gah-nah lo pre'tok ♪
♪ Cha Worf toh'gah-nah
lo pre'tok ♪
♪ Cha Worf
toh'gah-nah lo pre'tok ♪
♪ Tu mak dagh
cha doh borak! ♪
( laughter )
( applause )
That was not
a Klingon song.
It wasn't easy
to translate.
There doesn't seem to be
a Klingon word for "jolly."
It's traditional
for the birthday boy
to cut the cake.
Captain Picard sends
his birthday wishes.
He was needed
on the bridge.
Happy Birthday, Worf.
Thank you.
Ah...
A painting.
Yes, I have entered
my expressionist phase.
This is my interpretation
of the Battle of Haros.
The Battle of Haros.
I think
it's wonderful,
and I know just
where to put it.
What are you doing?
I always thought
this room could use
a little more color.
Nice. The Battle
of Haros, right?
Worf,
are you all right?
Yes... yes,
I think
Data's painting is
making me dizzy.
DR. CRUSHER :
Some cake?
Oh, thank you,
Doctor.
I... I thought
the cake was chocolate.
Don't I wish.
This is from Alexander.
He gave it to me
just before he left
to visit your parents.
Thank you.
What is it, Worf?
It's a cast of
Alexander's forehead--
the ridges
of a warrior.
TROI:
He wished he could
have been here
when you got back
from shore leave.
You should have
seen him, Worf.
He stayed up all night
talking about how proud
he was of his father.
Thank you for watching him
while I was away.
Oh, it was
my pleasure.
PICARD:
So, how old are you,
Mr. Worf?
Captain... I was told
you could not attend.
I wouldn't miss this
for the world.
How old are you?
I am...
Old enough.
( laughing )
Report.
The array appears to be
functioning normally, sir.
That can't be right.
We were told the array
stopped relaying data
six days ago.
The array is still
transmitting data, sir,
but it is no longer
sending that information
to the Federation.
It appears someone
has redirected
its imaging systems.
Where is the information
being sent now?
Sector 19658, sir.
I am unable to access
its main computer
so it is impossible
to determine
its exact location.
What's in that sector?
It is uninhabited,
but there could be
a ship or a subspace relay
station receiving the data.
Captain , I suggest we beam
a repair team aboard the Array.
We can begin downloading
their imaging logs,
find out what
the Array's been observing
for the past six days.
Make it so.
Mr. Data...
( quiet conversation )
Excuse me,
Counselor.
Do you have
a moment?
Of course.
I have been meaning to speak
with you about Alexander.
Oh?
It has never
been easy for me
having Alexander
on board.
I have tried to be
a good father,
to give him guidance,
but he seems to have
his own mind about some things.
Most children do.
I could not have come
this far without your help,
and Alexander
looks up to you.
At times, I have felt that
you were like a mother to him.
Worf, that's one
of the nicest things
anyone's ever said to me.
One time, when I thought
I was going to die,
I asked you
to watch over Alexander.
I was wondering
if you would consider
formalizing
that arrangement.
I want you to be
Alexander's soh-chlm.
His... soh-chlm?
You would become
his surrogate mother.
In case anything ever
happened to me,
you would be
responsible for him.
I don't know
what to say.
It's a great honor.
So, um, that would
make me your...
The closest analogy
is... stepsister.
That would make my mother
your stepmother.
I had not
considered that.
It is a risk
I am willing to take.
I accept.
DATA:
Lieutenant Worf,
please report
to Engineering.
I am on my way.
We have analyzed
the imaging logs.
It appears the Array
was reprogrammed
to observe several
Federation sites.
This is Deep Space 5,
Starbase 47,
the Iadara colony,
and the Utopia
Planitia shipyards.
They're responsible for
new starship development.
WORF:
Someone is
using the array
for covert surveillance
of the Federation.
That is our theory.
We believe
unauthorized access
was made six days ago.
The imaging logs
from that day
show a ship
approaching the array.
That is a Cardassian
ship, Galor-class.
We're only three light-years
from Cardassian space.
They would have easy
access to the array.
Mr. Worf, start
a long-range scan
of the region.
See if there are any
Cardassian ships nearby.
Aye, sir.
Worf, here's a propulsion
analysis
of the Cardassian
vessel.
You might try
scanning for its
energy configuration.
Lieutenant,
are you all right?
I feel dizzy.
Worf, you don't look
so good.
Maybe you ought
to go to Sick Bay.
Yes... yes,
perhaps I will.
Any nausea or
blurred vision?
No.
However, I did experience
some dizziness earlier today
at my birthday celebration.
Sounds like you're having
some of the side effects
from the concussion.
I can give you
some vertazine
for the dizziness,
but I'd like you to rest.
Doctor, perhaps
you are thinking
of another patient.
I have no concussion.
Worf, you came in here
this morning
complaining
of ringing in your ears.
I scanned you.
You had a concussion.
You don't remember
any of this?
No.
Temporary memory loss
is common for
this kind of injury.
Do you remember telling me
about the Bat'leth tournament?
You said that one
of the competitors
hit you over the head.
That's why you lost
the match.
I won that tournament,
and I can prove it to you!
What's wrong?
It says "ninth place."
This is not
the same trophy.
Someone is playing
a trick on me.
Worf, try to stay calm.
Memory loss can be
very disorienting.
The log...
I recorded a personal log
on my way back
to the Enterprise.
Computer, access personal logs
on shuttlecraft Curie.
Show my log entry
for Stardate 47391.2.
Personal log, Stardate 47391.2.
I am returning from the Bat'leth
competition on Forcas III.
The conditions were difficult.
Several contenders were maimed.
One of the contenders used
an illegal t'gha maneuver on me.
The judges chose to ignore it
and I was robbed
of my rightful standing.
I was awarded ninth place.
I am looking forward
to resuming my duties
aboard the En...
( stops playback )
I do not understand.
Worf, I'm sure
this is very
disturbing for you
but don't worry.
Your memories
will return.
Now, the best thing you
could do right now
is to settle back into
your normal routine,
but slowly.
Thank you, Doctor.
Let me know if you have
any more problems
with dizziness.
I'll give you
a hypospray.
Lieutenant...
Have you completed
the metallurgical scan
of the array?
Sir?
The metallurgical scan.
Have you completed it?
I do not remember
you asking me to...
( beeping )
Captain, there's a Cardassian
ship approaching--
Galor-class.
Open a channel.
On screen.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Starship Enterprise.
You are in Federation territory.
Please explain
your presence.
We were wondering
the same thing
about you, Captain.
Why would Starfleet's flagship
want to venture so close
to the Cardassian border?
We are repairing
one of our subspace telescopes.
I see.
May we offer our assistance?
No, thank you.
Everything is under control.
If you don't mind my asking,
what exactly is this telescope
of yours designed to do?
PICARD:
It is a long-range
subspace array.
We use it for gathering data
on astronomical phenomena.
I'm certain
it would never be used
to observe
a neighboring species.
Certainly not.
Well, then,
best of luck with your repairs.
Just try to make certain
that your studies are limited
to astronomical phenomena.
Charming fellow.
Captain,
that ship was responsible
for reprogramming
the array.
What are you saying?
It is the same class
and energy configuration
as the ship we saw
in the imaging logs.
The imaging logs?
Are you suggesting
that you have evidence
that the Cardassians
have tampered with the array?
They are using the array
as a surveillance device.
You saw the logs yourself.
I haven't heard
anything about this.
Neither have I.
Commander Data,
show them the logs
you downloaded from the array.
I know of no such logs.
Mr. Worf, are you
feeling all right?
Yes.
Mr. Data, perhaps you
had better reexamine
the array.
See if you can find
any evidence
to support
Mr. Worf's claims.
WORF:
Dr. Crusher says
I am experiencing
further memory loss,
but my instincts tell me
it is more than that.
I remember
those imaging logs.
I could tell you every
detail, every word!
Worf, let's assume for
a second you're right--
that things did happen
as you remember them.
Are you saying
that everyone's
memory on this ship
has been altered
but yours?
( door chimes )
Enter.
Counselor.
Worf, I wanted you to know
that we reexamined
the imaging logs.
They don't show
a Cardassian ship
or any evidence
that the array
was reprogrammed.
From what we can tell,
the array suffered
a simple mechanical failure.
That is not right!
I was certain that...
What's wrong?
Counselor,
the painting
that Commander Data gave me...
it has moved.
Worf, I hung
that painting there...
at your birthday party,
remember?
No...
The painting has changed.
Don't you see it?
Your hair, and
your clothing...
they have changed as well!
Worf, maybe you should come
with me to Sick Bay and...
Now, Mr. Worf.
( alarm blaring )
Now!
What are you waiting for?
Raise the shields!
This panel configuration
has been altered.
I do not know how...
( crash )
Direct hit,
Engineering Section and Deck 42.
Shield generators
are overloading.
Number One.
Firing photon torpedoes.
Full spread.
Direct hit
on their main reactor.
They're returning fire.
( crash )
Captain, we have sustained
heavy damage
to the deflector systems.
Hull breaches
on decks 17 and 36.
Ensign, take us out of here.
Maximum warp.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
Are they pursuing us?
No, sir.
They are firing
on the Argus Array.
They destroyed it, sir.
Bridge to engineering.
Mr. La Forge,
what's your status?
HAYES: This is
Ensign Hayes, sir.
Commander La Forge
has been taken to Sick Bay
with plasma burns.
There's serious damage
to the secondary plasma conduit,
but I think we've got it
under control.
Acknowledged.
Ensign, lay in a course
to Starbase 129.
Aye, sir.
What happened back there,
Mr. Worf?
I believe I experienced
another memory loss.
RIKER: Memory loss?
What are you
talking about?
I do not feel well.
Request permission
to be temporarily
relieved of duty, sir.
Granted.
Computer, access personal logs
on shuttlecraft Curie.
Play log entry
for Stardate 47391.2.
COMPUTER: There is no log entry
from the shuttlecraft Curie
for that Stardate.
Computer,
display any log entries
concerning the Bat'leth
tournament on Forcas III.
Personal log, Stardate 47391.2.
There has been a malfunction
in the ship's main deflector.
It will require
two more days of repairs.
As a result,
I will not be able to compete
in the Bat'leth tournament
on Forcas III.
I have asked my brother
to take my place.
He does not have my prowess
with the blade, but...
( stops playback )
( door chimes )
Why did you
lock the door?
Why shouldn't I?
I heard what happened
on the Bridge.
Are you all right?
I am not sure.
Do you want
to talk about it?
I would rather not,
Counselor.
Very well... Lieutenant.
Hot chocolate.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Actually, there is.
Come and sit down.
I just want you
to relax for a minute.
( sighs )
There.
You are so tense.
Now, I know you
don't want to talk
about what happened
on the bridge,
but there are times
when it's just best
to let things out.
Come on.
If you can't talk to me,
who can you talk to, hmm?
Agh!
I do not believe
this is appropriate behavior.
Even for your wife?
Wife?!
Worf, what's wrong?
I do not know.
Things are changing.
What's changed?
I do not remember us--
you and I-- being mates.
It is as if events
and circumstances
continue to change
from moment
to moment,
but I am the only one
who seems to be
aware of it.
Are you saying
you don't remember
the last three years?
You don't remember us
falling in love
and getting married?
I do remember
the last three years,
but they were different.
We did not have
this relationship.
We were friends.
And the Enterprise
did not have
a battle with
the Cardassians.
And no one believes me.
( sighs )
Whatever's wrong...
whatever happened...
I want you to know
that I believe you
and that I love you.
And together, we'll find out
what's happening.
I am initiating
a subspace scan
to search for
temporal anomalies
both on and off the ship.
OGAWA:
Counselor Troi,
please report to Sick Bay.
I'm on my way.
Let me know if
you find anything.
Commander, how long
have I been married
to Counselor Troi?
Two years, one
month, and 12 days.
And when did this
relationship begin?
It is my understanding
your romantic affiliation began
shortly after you recovered
from your spinal injury
on Stardate 45587.
It was six months later that
you asked commander Riker
for his formal permission
to court Counselor Troi.
You felt to do otherwise
would be
dishonorable.
And then we mated?
I am not privy
to the exact details
of when, where or how
your first coupling
took place.
I could investigate it.
No, that is all right.
I am detecting
no temporal anomalies
in this system.
Perhaps we should attempt
to pinpoint the exact moment
when events
became discontinuous.
Do you remember
the first change?
I was in Sick Bay.
Dr. Crusher told me
I had a concussion,
but I do not remember
that happening.
Think back-- are you certain
that was the very first change?
Before...
Yes. Yes, I was
in Engineering.
I felt a wave of dizziness,
and when I looked up,
you and Commander La Forge
were on the opposite side
of the room
and Captain Picard was gone.
I thought I had
blacked out for a moment
and had not observed
your movements.
And at my birthday party,
the cake was chocolate
and then it was yellow.
And Commander Riker told me
Captain Picard
was not going to attend,
and then suddenly
he was there.
Hmm... we should try to find
the commonalities
in these events.
Who were the people
you were with?
Everyone was
at my birthday party.
Then I was with Counselor Troi
then Commander La Forge
came in...
Geordi...
Geordi was present
at all three locations
and he was near me
in each case
just before
I noticed the differences.
There has to be a connection.
It is possible.
We should speak
to Commander
La Forge.
Doctor, is Geordi well enough
to answer a few questions?
Geordi's dead.
There do not appear to be
any unusual readings.
Energy residuals
from the plasma burns,
the beginnings of
cellular decomposition...
I see nothing that connects
these bio-readings
to your recent sense
of discontinuity.
What about
his visor?
I still see nothing unusual.
Perhaps we should activate it.
Hook it up
to the diagnostic array
and I'll
check it out.
The visor is active.
Worf, are you
all right?
Have you noticed
another discontinuity?
Dr. Crusher
was not here.
Dr. Ogawa was.
Doctor Ogawa?
And my uniform has changed.
What is my rank
and position?
TROI:
You're a commander
and first officer.
Are... we still married?
Yes.
DATA:
I am detecting
a quantum flux
in your cellular RNA.
What does that mean?
I do not know.
I will have to analyze
these readings.
I have found
that the quantum flux
in Worf's cellular RNA
extends
to the subatomic level.
It is asynchronous
with normal matter.
In essence, Captain,
Mr. Worf does not belong
in our universe.
What?
All matter
in the universe
resonates on a quantum level
with a unique signature.
That signature is constant.
It cannot be changed
through any
known process.
It is the basic foundation
of existence.
Are you saying that
Worf's quantum signature
is different from ours?
Yes, sir.
I cannot explain it.
It is as if he originates from
a different quantum universe.
Mr. Worf, you say the
discontinuities started
to occur after you returned
from a Bat'leth tournament
on Forcas III.
Yes, sir.
Now, I know for a fact
that you never attended
that tournament, and
that no shuttlecraft
has left the Enterprise
for over a month.
I understand that,
but I also clearly remember
attending the tournament
and returning to the ship
in a shuttlecraft.
Do you remember the route
you took to return?
Yes.
Let's backtrack
that course.
See if there are any
unusual readings
or anomalies.
DATA: Aye, sir.
If I may inquire, sir
how long have you been Captain
of the Enterprise?
Four years.
Ever since
Captain Picard was killed
in the incident with the Borg.
You don't remember
any of this, do you?
I do remember.
I just remember it differently.
Captain,
I'm picking up a minor
subspace disturbance
off the port bow.
Full stop.
MAN: Aye, sir.
Analysis, Mr. Data.
It appears to be
a quantum fissure
in the space-time continuum.
On screen.
DATA:
The anomaly cannot be seen,
but I believe
I can enhance it
with a warp field
to make it visible.
RIKER:
Is it dangerous?
DATA:
Not from this distance, sir.
I am also detecting
an ion trail
intersecting
the phenomenon.
I believe it was left
by a Starfleet
type-6 shuttlecraft.
So I was here.
I have an
explanation, sir.
I believe the quantum
fissure we discovered
is a fixed point across
the space-time continuum--
a keyhole which intersects
many other quantum realities.
What do you mean,
"quantum realities"?
For any event,
there is an infinite number
of possible outcomes.
Our choices determine
which outcomes will follow,
but there is a theory
in quantum physics
that all possibilities
that can happen, do happen
in alternate
quantum realities.
And somehow I have
been shifting
from one reality
to another.
That is correct.
How did
this happen?
When Worf's shuttlecraft
came into contact
with the quantum fissure,
I believe its warp engines
caused a small break
in the barriers
between quantum realities.
Worf was thrown into
a state of quantum flux.
He immediately shifted
into other realities.
And Geordi's visor
somehow triggered that effect.
Exactly.
The visor uses
a subspace field pulse.
I believe that whenever
Geordi came near Worf
the field pulse intensified
the quantum flux
and pushed Worf
into another reality.
Well, how can we find
my original quantum state
and return me too it?
WES:
We could scan
the quantum fissure
using a subspace
differential pulse.
Maybe we could find
the quantum state
that shares
Worf's signature
and find a way
to get him back.
An excellent idea,
Lieutenant.
Worf...
from what I understand,
there's a good chance
my Worf won't return.
I guess it's just hard
for me to accept
that there's a reality out
there where you never loved me.
Deanna, I have always
considered you a close friend.
And although I have never
seriously considered
a romantic relationship,
I would not be opposed
to the possibility.
What about our children?
Children?
You didn't know?
When the last shift
occurred in Sick Bay,
we did not have any children.
We have a little girl,
Shannara.
She's two years old.
And a three-year-old boy,
Eric-Christopher.
What about Alexander?
Alexander?
He was my son
in another reality.
I've used
a differential pulse
to analyze over 10
million quantum states
within the fissure,
but I still haven't found
one with your signature.
This may take
some time, sir.
Captain, a Bajoran ship
is approaching.
RIKER:
Red alert.
The Bajorans?
Ever since
the Bajorans
overpowered the
Cardassian empire,
they've become more
and more aggressive.
Yesterday, they destroyed
one of our subspace telescopes
because they thought
we were using it to
spy against them.
They're charging
their weapons, sir.
Shields!
( blast, crash )
Return fire.
They've damaged
our power systems, sir.
It's caused an energy surge
within the subspace pulse.
The quantum fissure
is beginning to destabilize.
Can we disengage the pulse?
( blast, crash )
WES:
Too late, sir.
What the hell is happening?
The barriers between quantum
realities are breaking down.
Other realities are
emerging into our own.
The Bajoran ship
is disengaging, sir.
The rate of quantum incursions
is increasing exponentially.
At this rate, the sector
will be completely filled
with Enterprises
within three days.
Captain, we're receiving
285,000 hails.
I wish I knew
what to tell them.
Mr. Data, can we stop
these incursions?
Perhaps. If we
can find the ship
that matches Commander Worf's
quantum signature.
How would that help?
It was Worf's shuttlecraft
which traversed the fissure
and weakened the barriers
between quantum realities.
If he reenters the fissure
in his original shuttle
and emits
a broad-spectrum warp field,
it may be enough
to seal the fissure
and stop additional realities
from entering our own.
What then?
How do we get
the Enterprises
that are already here
back to where they belong?
In theory,
the act of sealing the fissure
should restore the barriers
between quantum states.
The ships would return
to their own realities.
Lieutenant Crusher,
send a general hail--
all ships.
CRUSHER: Aye, sir.
This is Captain Riker
of the Enterprise.
That is, the Enterprise,
that is indigenous
to this universe.
We've all encountered
a quantum anomaly.
We think we have
found a way
to return us all
to our proper realities,
but we need to find
that ship
which exhibits
a certain quantum signature.
Our Mr. Data will transmit
that signature to you now.
( multiple communication beeps )
Anything?
There's too much
com traffic, sir.
It's tough to isolate
who's talking to who.
Wait a minute.
Here it is.
Someone's
responding.
On screen.
Captain, it would appear
that we have found
the quantum signature
you were looking for.
RIKER: Data believes
that by sending Worf back
through the fissure again,
it would return us all
to our proper realities.
Our Data has said
the same thing.
We need you to send us
your shuttlecraft Curie.
We're launching it now.
Thank you.
It's good to see you
again, Captain.
It's been a long time.
RIKER:
Did they send
the right shuttle?
Yes, sir.
It matches Commander Worf's
quantum signature precisely.
I have remodulated
the shuttle's engines
to emit an inverse warp field.
You will need to activate
that field
at the precise moment
you enter the fissure.
Assuming it works,
will I find myself
near my own ship?
That is one possibility.
However, the uncertainty
principle
dictates that time is
a variable in this equation.
You may end up
several days before the event
or several days after.
There is no way to tell.
I understand.
Good luck.
Setting course for the fissure.
RIKER:
Acknowledged.
( crash )
Captain, the shuttlecraft
is under attack.
The Bajorans again.
No, sir. It's one
of the Enterprises.
They're hailing us.
On screen.
We won't go back.
You don't know what it's like
in our universe.
The Federation's gone!
The Borg is everywhere!
We're one of
the last ships left.
Please, you've got to help us!
I'm sorry, there's no choice.
If this works,
everything
will return...
No! We won't go back!
Sir, they're firing
on the shuttlecraft.
Open fire.
Try to disable them.
Direct hit.
Their shields
have collapsed.
Their engine core's
overloading.
What happened?
It looks like the ship had
already taken heavy damage.
Their warp containment field
must have been weak.
Probably from fighting
with the Borg.
Captain, Worf is
entering the fissure.
Charging primary systems.
Initiating inverse warp field.
Worf to Enterprise.
PICARD:
Enterprise here.
Captain,
is everything all right?
Yes, Lieutenant.
Is there a problem?
No, I do not believe so,
but I will explain
when I arrive.
How was the Bat'leth tournament?
It was fine, sir.
I won champion standing.
So, you think
this quantum fissure
is nothing that we
need to worry about?
No, no, I believe
the inverse warp
field resealed it.
I'm looking forward
to reading your report.
Something wrong?
I know what you
are planning, sir.
I will not be surprised.
Surprised? I don't know
what you're talking about.
Of course you don't.
Welcome home, Worf.
Uhh!
I hope you don't mind
I let myself in.
I promised Alexander
I'd feed his
Dalvan hissing beetle
while you were both away.
So, you do not live here?
What's that supposed
to mean?
It is a long story.
Happy birthday, Worf.
Will wanted to give you
a surprise party, but I knew
you'd hate it, so I
talked him out of it.
Thank you.
I know Klingons
like to be alone
on their birthdays.
You probably want
to meditate
or hit yourself with
a painstik or something.
Deanna...
You do not
have to leave.
Oh?
I... have not
had dinner.
Would you care
to... join me?
I'd love to.
Champagne.