I don't see why we have
to do this every year.
I thought that last year
the teachers had agreed
that they wouldn't
do this anymore.
"Captain Picard Day"
is one of the children's
favorite school activities.
They look forward
to it all year.
Why does it
have to be me?
Because you're
the captain
and they look
up to you.
You're a role
model for them.
Well...
they seem to have
a somewhat exaggerated
impression of me.
( imitating Picard ):
I don't know,
I think the resemblance
is rather striking.
Wouldn't you agree,
Number One?
Isn't there something
else you have to do?
I'll be on the bridge.
Will.
The finalists will be
here in half an hour.
You have to pick a first,
second and third place
and four
honorable mentions.
Worf to Captain.
Incoming transmission
from Admiral Blackwell.
It is coded priority one.
Put it through, Mr. Worf.
Excuse me, Counselor.
Yes, Admiral?
Captain, what is your status?
We are conducting
energy output studies
of the Merkoria Quasar.
All systems normal.
The ship is fully operational.
Good. I'm postponing
the quasar study for the moment.
The Enterprise is to rendezvous
with the Starship Crazy Horse
in sector 1607 immediately.
You're authorized to exceed
warp speed limitations
for the duration
of this assignment.
I understand.
What is our assignment?
I prefer not to discuss it
over subspace channels.
The Crazy Horse will be
carrying someone
from Starfleet Intelligence.
He'll brief you
when he arrives.
Very well.
"Captain Picard Day"?
Oh, uh...
Yes, it's, uh...
it's for the children.
I'm a...
I'm a role model.
I'm sure you are.
Starfleet out.
So who won the contest?
Oh. Paul Menegay,
a seven year old.
He did a most interesting
clay sculpture of my head.
Was that the orange one
with the lumpy skin?
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you'll be interested
to know that I've arranged
for a "Commander Riker Day"
next month.
I'm even considering
making an entry myself.
Great.
Energize.
MAN:
Aye, sir.
Will!
I'll bet you never
thought you'd
see me again.
It's good
to see you, sir.
Yeah, sure it is.
You look like you're
about to faint.
No. It's... it's just
that it's been a long time.
Uh, Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
Admiral Eric Pressman.
Pressman... yes, of course.
You were Will's first
commanding officer.
On the... the Pegasus.
That's right.
As a matter of fact, the Pegasus
is the reason I'm here.
Sir?
She's still out there, Will
and the Romulans
have found her.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out
new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
♪♪
As you know,
the Starship Pegasus
was lost in this sector
some 12 years ago
along with most of her crew.
I was her captain
and Commander Riker
here was my helmsman.
I remember
hearing about it.
The ship
was destroyed
by a warp core
breach, as I recall.
The captain and I
along with seven others
managed to make it
to the escape pod
before the breach
became critical.
From space, we observed
what appeared to be
a matter/antimatter explosion
which vaporized the ship.
No wreckage was found
so Starfleet officially
declared the ship destroyed.
However,
all that changed
three days ago.
Starfleet Intelligence
has an operative
in Romulan high command.
He sent us a message
that a Romulan warbird
had located
a piece of debris
in the Devolin system
which was positively
identified as being
from the Pegasus.
The warbird was then ordered
to locate the rest of the ship
if possible and retrieve it.
What would
the Romulans want
with pieces of a
12-year-old starship?
The Pegasus was a prototype--
experimental engine,
new weapons systems.
In fact, some of our
designs were used
in constructing
the Enterprise.
There are a lot
of things on board
the Romulans would love
to get their hands on.
What are our orders?
To find the ship
before the Romulans do.
Salvage it if possible,
destroy it if necessary.
You command the Enterprise
while I remain in command
of the overall mission.
We'll need metallurgical
and chromographic specs
on the Pegasus in order
to set up the proper
search parameters.
I'll make the appropriate
information available to you.
Very well.
Lay in a course
for the Devolin system.
Aye, sir.
♪♪
Captain, we are
approaching the
Devolin system.
Any sign of the Romulans?
No, sir.
PRESSMAN:
Oh, they're out there.
They're just waiting to see
what you're going to do.
Mr. La Forge?
There's an awful lot of
ionizing radiation
in this system, Captain.
That and the amount of sheer
rock, that's going to
slow down our
search a little.
How slow?
I'd say at least...
WORF:
Sir, Romulan warbird
decloaking directly ahead.
They are powering weapons.
Shields up.
Red alert.
Prepare phasers.
Sir, they are
hailing us.
On screen.
I am Commander Sirol
of the Romulan vessel Terix.
To whom do I have
the honor of speaking?
I am Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship Enterprise.
Captain Picard,
I've heard so much about you.
A pleasure to make
your acquaintance.
I hope our sudden appearance
didn't startle you.
Not at all.
But your unannounced appearance
might have
unfortunate consequences.
It would be an awful shame
if your ship were damaged
due to some misunderstanding.
I am touched by your concern
for my ship
but I doubt we were
ever in any danger.
May I ask what you are doing
in this system?
I might ask you
the same question.
We are conducting a survey
of gaseous anomalies.
How interesting.
So are we.
Perhaps we could combine
our efforts
and share our findings.
I doubt our objectives
are compatible.
Perhaps you're right.
This has been
a most pleasant conversation
but we must return
to our research.
Then I won't keep you.
( console beeping )
Sir, they are
moving off
resuming their tachyon scans
of the system.
Stand down red alert
but keep tracking
their movement,
Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Commander, how long
will it take us
to search this system?
LA FORGE:
At least seven
days, sir.
WORF:
And the Romulans have
a two-day head start.
Then let's get to it.
Mr. Data?
Initiating sensor sweep
of grid 01.
So how long have
you had that beard?
About four years.
I got tired of hearing
how young I looked.
What was it that...
Lieutenant Boylen
used to call you?
"Ensign baby face."
( chuckling )
You never did
have much of
a sense of humor.
I like to think that I've
lightened up a little
in my old age.
Really?
I've been known
to tell a joke or two.
Well, it's about time.
You were always so
serious on the Pegasus.
Well...
We went through
some serious times.
Do you really think
we're going to find
the Pegasus again?
I wouldn't have come all
the way out here if I didn't.
What about the experiment?
Do you think we're going
to find that, too?
Maybe.
You know, I think a lot
about what happened...
especially on that last day.
So do I.
It's not the
kind of thing
you just forget.
Do you ever wonder
if we did the right thing?
Never.
What happened was
a tragedy, yes
but it wasn't your fault
and it wasn't mine.
What we were doing was for
the good of the Federation
and we can't
blame ourselves
if the others
couldn't see that.
I know, but...
maybe we went about it
the wrong way.
Well, this time
we may have a chance
to do it
the right way.
If this mission is successful
if we find the Pegasus
and the experiment
we can finish what we started
12 years ago.
You want to try again?
It's not
just me, Will.
The chief of Starfleet Security
has personally given me
her assurance
of complete support.
Admiral Ranar!
How many other people
know about this?
Not many, and it's up to us
to make sure
it stays that way.
Ranar has given me
written orders for you.
You'll find them coded
in the Enterprise computer.
You've been instructed
not to reveal
the true nature
of our mission to anyone else
not even Captain Picard.
Will... don't worry.
It won't be like it was
12 years ago
and this time,
no one's going to stop us.
♪♪
As a matter of fact,
I never met Will
until he reported on board
at Farpoint Station.
You chose your
first officer
without ever
meeting him?
I was looking
through the records
of about 50 candidates
and Will's was very much
like all the others--
filled with lots
of dry statistics
and glowing letters
of recommendation
that tell you nothing.
I was about
to put it aside
and look at another
file, and then...
something caught my eye.
There was an incident
on Altair III
when Will was first
officer of the Hood.
He refused to let
Captain Desoto beam down
during a crisis.
He disobeyed
a direct order
and he risked a
general court-martial
because he thought
he was right.
And when I read that,
I knew that I had found
my Number One.
You wanted someone
with a history of disobedience?
I wanted someone who
would stand up to me
someone who
was more concerned
with the safety of the ship
and accomplishing the mission
than with how it might
look on his record.
To me, that's one of the marks
of a good officer.
Frankly, I've always felt
it was more important
for an officer
to trust his captain's judgment.
In a crisis, there's no time
for explanations.
Orders have to be
obeyed without question
or lives may be lost.
I am aware of that, Admiral.
Of course you are.
I guess this mission
has brought up
some old ghosts for me.
You know what it's like
to lose a ship?
You're always wondering
if there's something else
you should have done.
Something you missed.
Admiral,
the record regarding
the loss of the Pegasus is...
a bit vague
from the moment
just before you abandoned ship.
Is there anything
that you can add
to the official account?
I'm afraid not.
But I can tell you this--
12 years ago,
I needed an officer
that I could count on
in a crisis
someone who would support
and obey my decisions
without question
someone who was willing
to trust my judgment
and that someone was Will Riker.
Without his loyalty,
none of us would have survived.
( groaning )
What's wrong?
I think I
busted a rib.
Excuse me.
What were you doing?
I was doing bat'leth
moves with Mr. Worf.
I jabbed when
I should have blocked.
He caught me right
in the side.
It's a good thing we
were using the sticks
instead of
the real blades.
It's broken, all right.
Give him ten cc's
of terakine
for the pain.
I can't believe
how stupid I was.
You both must
have gotten
a little carried
away, that's all.
No, it was my fault.
I got distracted
at a crucial moment.
It can happen to anyone.
I knew what I was supposed
to do and I didn't do it.
If those had been
real bat'leths
I might be dead right now.
There, all better.
Will, it's all right.
You made a mistake.
No harm done.
You'll be
better next time.
Yeah. Maybe.
Scan of grid 157
is complete.
I am moving
to grid 158.
The Romulan warship is
still searching grid 270.
They're sure spending
a lot of time over there.
I wonder if they...?
LA FORGE:
Commander,
I think we might
have just struck pay dirt.
There's a subspace
resonance signature
coming from that asteroid.
From the frequency variances
it looks like the pattern
of a Federation warp core.
Captain Picard
to the bridge.
Take us to within
ten kilometers
of asteroid
gamma 601.
Geordi's found
something.
There's a subspace
resonance signature
coming from
that asteroid.
It could be the warp core
of the Pegasus.
I think he's right.
I recognize some of
the variance patterns.
Put the asteroid
on the main viewscreen.
DATA:
I have confirmed
Geordi's readings.
The resonance signature
is originating
from somewhere beneath
the asteroid's surface.
Beneath the surface?
How is that possible?
The asteroid contains
several deep chasms
large enough
for a starship to enter.
It is possible
the Pegasus drifted
into the asteroid's
gravitational field
and was pulled down
into one of the fissures.
Sir, the Romulan warbird
has altered course
once again.
They are heading
toward our position.
They probably want to see
what we're so interested
in over here.
Mr. Data, how long
will it take
to determine the location
of the Pegasus?
At least another
six hours, sir.
That's too long.
If the Romulans start
searching the asteroid
they could find the
ship before we do.
I recommend we destroy
the asteroid.
It would take most
of our photon torpedoes
but it would preclude
any possibility
of the Pegasus falling
into Romulan hands.
Our top priority
is to salvage the
ship, Commander.
I'll consider destroying
it only as a last resort.
Yes, sir.
Captain...
could you give me
a third alternative?
Mr. Data, would it be possible
to saturate the asteroid
with Verteron Particles?
That would mask
the resonance signature
and prevent the Romulans
from detecting it.
In order for the deception
to succeed
it would have to appear
to be a natural phenomenon.
Verteron Particles
are artificial in nature.
Wait a minute.
We can blanket the asteroid
with high levels
of ionizing radiation.
There's so much of it
in the system already
the Romulans won't know
the difference.
Mr. Data?
Theoretically, sir,
it should work.
If we do this,
we have to do it fast.
The Romulans will be
within sensor range
in less than a minute.
Make it so, Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
Initiating ionization
field pulse.
When he's finished,
we'll have to move away
and make it look as if
we've scanned the asteroid
but haven't found anything.
Lay in a course
for the next search grid.
Stand by to engage.
If it works, the Romulans
won't find anything
and we can return later.
If it doesn't...
If it doesn't work
we'll have handed them
the Pegasus.
Ionization pulse
complete.
Helm, one quarter impulse.
Engage.
The Romulans
are initiating
a tachyon scan
of the asteroid.
They have switched to
their lateral sensor array.
Beginning another scan.
They're certainly
being thorough.
DATA:
The warbird has completed
its sensor sweep.
If they found
the resonance signature
they should be sending
away teams any second.
DATA:
They are moving out.
Mr. Data, we must convince
the Romulans
that we're still
looking for the Pegasus.
I want you
to continue
scanning this system.
Aye, sir.
I want to be back at this
asteroid at 0800 hours tomorrow.
Plan your search
pattern accordingly.
Aye, sir.
Admiral, would you care
to join me for some late dinner?
Please excuse me, Captain
but I think I'd better
turn in early.
You have the bridge,
Number One.
Oh, and will you bring
the scan analysis
to my quarters when
you're off watch?
Aye, sir.
Initiate search
of grid 163.
Beginning sensor sweeps.
Commander, I want to
see you in the
captain's ready room.
Mr. Data, you have
the bridge.
Aye, sir.
What the hell is
the matter with you?
Destroy the Pegasus before
we've even taken a look at it?
I thought it was
more important
that the Romulans...
Well, you were wrong!
We have a chance here
to change
the balance
of power in this quadrant
but we can't
very well do that
if we destroy the Pegasus,
now, can we?
No, sir.
It hasn't been easy
for you, I'm sure
keeping your captain
and friends
in the dark like this.
I haven't enjoyed it,
if that's what you mean.
I hope you understand
that it's necessary.
I understand that you
think it's necessary.
You have changed.
Changed?
Something the captain
and I were talking about.
To be honest, I'm glad to see
this kind of change
in you, Will.
State your opinion
and stand by it.
It's a far cry
from the young man
who used to sit at my helm
and worry about pressing
the wrong button.
A lot of things can change
in 12 years, Admiral.
Yes, they can.
But it's important
that a man changes
the right things in his life--
not his sense of duty,
not his sense of loyalty.
I'd like to think that I haven't
changed those things, sir.
I would like
to think that, too
because those things
say more about a man
than the rank on his collar
or the uniform he wears.
They define him.
12 years ago, a lot of older
and more seasoned officers
turned away from their duty
but you stood up
for what was right.
I'm sorry, Will.
I know the kind
of man you are.
I know that I can
count on you again.
( door chimes )
Come.
The scan analysis
you asked for.
Thank you.
( sighs )
Is there something else, sir?
Yes, there is.
"Judge Advocate General's
report, Stardate 36764.
"Subject: inquiry into mutiny
"aboard
USS Pegasus.
"Based on testimony
"from Captain Pressman
and other surviving officers
"the judge advocate believes
there is sufficient evidence
"to conclude
that certain members of the crew
"did mutiny
against the captain
just prior to the destruction
of the Pegasus."
Mutiny?
On a Federation
starship?
That's shocking,
it's unthinkable.
And yet you've never
mentioned it.
No, sir.
You know, it wasn't easy
to get this report.
I had to pull in
quite a few favors at Starfleet
just to get a look at it.
It seems that
it was classified
by Starfleet
Intelligence.
So...
not only...
was the Pegasus
carrying sensitive equipment
which must not be allowed
to fall into Romulan hands,
not only was there
a mysterious explosion
which seemed to destroy
the ship,
but didn't...
but it seems that there
was a mutiny on board.
Now, I've read
the official report
of the inquiry
on that mutiny
but I want to know
your version of what happened.
I was on the bridge.
The ship was at
yellow alert.
We were running some tests
on the engines.
Something went wrong.
There was an explosion
in engineering.
Heavy casualties.
In the midst of this crisis
the first officer,
the chief of engineering
and most of the bridge crew
mutinied against
Captain Pressman.
Why?
They thought he
was jeopardizing the ship.
And you?
I was seven months
out of the academy
my head still ringing
with words like
"duty" and "honor."
when they turned on him
I thought they were a bunch of
self-serving, disloyal officers
so I grabbed a phaser
and I defended my captain.
Two or three others joined us,
but it was clear by then
that the mutineers had
most of the crew behind them.
We felt a need
to get off the ship.
There was a running firefight
all the way
to the escape pod.
About five minutes
after we left the ship...
there was an explosion.
"The judge advocate
also believes
"that the surviving officers
are deliberately
"withholding vital information
from this inquiry.
Further investigation
is recommended."
Will, there was
no further investigation.
This report was classified,
and then it was quietly buried.
Why?
Sir, may I suggest
you take this up with Admiral...
I'm taking this up
with you, Will!
The judge advocate thought
that you were participating
in a conspiracy
to cover up the truth.
Now, what the hell
is going on here, Will?
Why did that mutiny happen?
Why is Pressman
so determined
to find your ship
12 years later?
I've said all I can.
I'm under direct orders
from Admiral Pressman
not to discuss this, sir.
Very well.
He's an admiral.
I'm a captain.
I cannot force you
to disobey his orders.
Therefore, I will have to remain
in the dark on this mission.
And I will
just have to trust
that you will not
let Pressman put this ship
at unnecessary risk.
And if I find that that trust
has been misplaced,
then I will have to reevaluate
the command structure
of this ship.
Dismissed.
( doors opening, closing )
♪♪
Captain, Starfleet places
the highest priority
on the success
of this mission.
Your request for a delay
is denied.
Margaret, something's
very wrong here.
Do you know what's going on?
I know that the chief
of Starfleet
Intelligence herself
is watching this one, Jean-Luc.
So, you'd be well advised
to follow Pressman's orders
and leave it at that.
Starfleet out.
( alert beeps )
Worf to Captain Picard.
We are approaching
asteroid gamma 601, sir.
On my way.
Mr. Worf, where
are the Romulans?
They're out
of sensor range
on the far side
of the system.
Take us to within
15 kilometers
of the asteroid and
hold that position.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Data, report.
For the past several hours
I have been scanning
the area where we
detected the resonance
signature of the Pegasus.
From the strength and polarity
of the signature
it would appear that most of
the warp core is still intact.
If we're lucky, the entire
engineering section
could be down there.
But how do we get to it?
I wouldn't want to
try to transport
through that much solid rock.
Agreed.
What about a shuttle?
We could send it down
through one of those fissures.
I would recommend
against it, sir.
There may be gravimetric
or magnetic fluctuations
inside the asteroid
which would overpower
the engines of a shuttlecraft.
Sounds like the best solution
is to take the Enterprise in.
Into the asteroid?
That's right.
Put this fissure
on the main viewer.
This chasm is large enough
for us to maneuver in.
Besides, if we ever hope
to salvage the Pegasus
we're going to need
a starship to do it.
Mr. Data?
It is theoretically
possible, sir,
but I am unaware
of any prior situations
where a starship
was taken so deeply
inside a planetary body.
There may be
unforeseen
difficulties.
Admiral, I don't think
that we can risk...
I've made my decision.
Prepare to take
the Enterprise in, Captain.
That's an order.
( sighs )
Mr. Data, will you please
note in the ship's log
that this action is being taken
over my explicit objection?
It is so noted, sir.
PICARD:
Yellow alert.
RIKER:
Shields up.
Inertial dampeners at maximum.
Ensign Gates, plot
a course into the chasm
maneuvering
thrusters only.
Course plotted, sir.
Take us in.
We are now two kilometers
beneath the surface.
Captain, we are
encountering shifts
in the magnetic
field density.
Admiral, if this passage
narrows to less
than 500 meters
I will abort
the mission.
You can charge me with
insubordination if you wish
but I'm not going
to risk the Enterprise
for a salvage operation.
Captain, I am reading
a large resonance
signature directly ahead.
Pegasus.
What the hell
happened?
DATA:
sensors show the ship
is still intact.
However, 65% of it is
contained within the asteroid.
It looks
as if half the ship
materialized
inside solid rock.
Yes, sir. I do not understand
how this could have happened.
Let's keep the speculation
to a minimum.
We have to begin
the salvage operation.
The equipment we need
was in main engineering.
Can you scan that section
of the Pegasus?
The starboard bulkhead
of main engineering
is contained
within the rock face
but most of its compartment
is still intact.
There is a hull breach
in that section.
If we begin
a power transfer
can we restore
life-support systems
to that compartment?
I believe so, sir.
The breach can be
temporarily sealed
by extending
our shields.
See to it.
Once you've restored
life-support
Commander Riker
and I will beam
directly into engineering.
Admiral,
I would like to
send down
a complete away team.
There's some very sensitive
equipment over there.
I don't want
anyone else near it.
Yes, sir.
This room was open
to space for 12 years.
The vacuum
preserved everything.
( console beeping )
I wonder how many of the crew
are buried back there.
PRESSMAN:
We're not here
for a memorial service.
( scanner beeping )
It's still intact.
( clattering )
What's the matter, Will?
Don't you understand?
We found it!
I know.
I kept hoping
it wouldn't be here...
that it had been destroyed...
that it was buried
in that rock back there.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
It means that I can't
put this off any longer.
Right up to this moment,
I had the luxury of time
but now I've got
to make a choice.
And, Admiral...
I'm afraid my choice
is this--
I can't let you start
these experiments again.
It was wrong 12 years ago,
and it is wrong today.
You had better reconsider
that position, Commander.
We have a mission
to accomplish
and you're going
to carry it out.
That's all you care about--
starting these
damn experiments again.
Look around-- this room
is filled with dead bodies.
These people died
because of this thing.
Keep your self-righteous
comments to yourself.
I knew most of these people
a lot longer than you did.
Yes, it was tragic,
but it was their fault.
You don't know that.
Neither of us knows
what happened after we left.
Well, it's not
hard to guess.
They tried to shut down
an experiment
they didn't understand.
Something went wrong,
and it killed them.
No, we killed them.
Now, that doesn't sound like
the same man
who grabbed a phaser
and defended his captain
12 years ago.
I've had 12 years
to think about it.
And if I had it
to do over again
I would have grabbed the phaser
and pointed it at you,
instead of them.
So, on reflection
you'd rather be a
traitor than a hero.
I wasn't a hero,
and neither were you.
What you did was wrong,
and I was wrong to support you
but I was too young and too
stupid to realize it.
You were the captain,
I was the ensign.
I was just following orders.
And if you hadn't,
you'd be dead right now
along with all
the rest of them.
Dead because you listened
to a bunch of mutinous cowards
who were too blinded by fear
to see what I was trying to do.
They were brave enough
to risk their lives
to stop you
from violating a treaty
the Federation signed
in good faith.
That treaty has bound our hands
and given the Romulans
a tactical advantage
for the last 60 years.
I was simply trying
to level the playing field.
And now you want
to try it again.
How many people will die
this time--
50, 100, 1,000?
All right, you don't want
to help me, fine.
But you are still
under my direct orders
not to talk about
what you know
and I expect you to follow
those orders to the letter.
I made you, mister
and I can break you
just as easily.
Do you understand
me, Commander?
Picard to away team.
Prepare to return
to the ship immediately.
Stand by, Enterprise.
Pressman to Enterprise.
Two people and one piece
of equipment to beam up.
( alarm blaring )
Report.
The Romulans have destroyed
the entrance to the chasm
with their disruptors.
They've sealed
us in.
WORF:
Sir, there is
an incoming message.
It is from the warbird.
On screen.
Aye, sir.
Captain, you seem to be
in a very unfortunate
circumstance.
How can we help?
Are you responsible for this?
I'm not sure.
We were conducting
some geological experiments
on the surface
of the asteroid.
It is entirely possible
that we accidentally
sealed you in.
If only we had known
you were beneath the surface--
if you had shared
your plans with us--
this might
have been avoided.
What do you want, Sirol?
I don't want
anything, Captain,
but I will offer to help you.
How?
By transporting
your crew aboard my ship.
We'll take you
back to Romulus
where, after a short stay
as our guests
you will be returned
to the Federation.
Thank you
for your generous offer.
I will take it
under advisement.
As you wish.
We will be continuing
our research in this system
for a while longer.
I await your decision.
We can't do it.
If we abandon
the Enterprise
they'll come back here
and get their hands
on both ships.
Agreed. Options?
WORF:
Captain, I believe
we could use
the phasers to cut our way out.
The asteroid's internal
structure is highly unstable.
Any attempt to cut
through the rock could cause
the entire chasm
to collapse.
Captain, I have
a suggestion.
There's a piece of equipment
in Admiral Pressman's quarters
under guard that might
get us out of here.
It's a prototype for
a Federation cloaking device.
You just ended
your career, Will.
That's what it's about.
A cloaking device.
In the Treaty of Algeron
the Federation
specifically agreed
not to develop
cloaking technology.
And that treaty is
the biggest mistake
we ever made.
It's kept us from
exploiting a vital
area of defense.
That treaty has kept us
in peace for 60 years--
and, as a Starfleet officer,
you're supposed to uphold it.
Now, that's enough!
I'm taking command
of this vessel.
Mr. Worf, escort the captain
to his quarters.
I don't think
anyone's going to
come to your defense
this time.
How do we use
the cloak to escape
from the asteroid?
It's more than just a cloak.
It changes the structure
of matter.
In theory,
a ship using this device
could pass through
normal matter.
I see why you were
so eager to find it.
Then, can't you see
the potential here?
The phasing cloak could be
the greatest breakthrough
in weapons research
in the last 50 years.
Except that it's illegal.
It's in violation
of an agreement
that the Federation
signed in good faith.
Captain, I think we could
adapt the cloak
for the Enterprise.
Mr. Data?
Theoretically,
it is possible, sir
but it would take several hours
to study the device
and determine how to link it
to our systems.
Make it so.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47457.1.
We have been trapped
inside the asteroid
for over eight hours.
Mr. Data and Commander La Forge
inform me
that they are nearly ready
to engage the cloak.
Commander, we've routed
the impulse engines
through the plasma conduits
but you're going to have
to watch the intercooler levels.
If they get too high
we'll blow the entire
relay system.
RIKER:
Understood.
I think that's what happened
12 years ago.
The cloak blew out
the plasma relays
on the Pegasus
after we left the ship.
The plasma ignited in space,
and it looked
as if the ship
had been destroyed.
So the ship drifted
into this system
still in a phased state
and when it passed
through this asteroid...
The cloak failed.
And half of the ship
materialized in solid rock.
La Forge to bridge.
The cloak is on line
and ready to begin
phase sequencing.
Proceed, Number One.
Aye, sir.
Activating power systems.
Report.
The cloak appears to be
functioning normally.
The ship's matter/energy
phasing rate
should be sufficient
to pass through the asteroid.
Take us out.
Maneuvering thrusters only.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
We will reach the rock face
in five seconds.
We have passed through
two kilometers
of the asteroid.
Now within one kilometer
of the surface.
We're approaching
the surface.
We have cleared
the asteroid, Captain.
The warbird is off
the port bow.
They're still waiting for us
to make up our minds.
Disengage the cloaking device,
Commander.
You cannot do that!
If the Romulans see us
decloaking, they'll...
They'll know
the truth, Admiral!
Which is what everyone
will know very shortly.
Carry out my orders.
Mr. Worf,
send a message to the warbird.
Inform them that
their government
will be contacted shortly
about this incident.
Aye, sir.
Admiral,
I am hereby charging you
with violation of
the Treaty of Algeron.
As captain of the Enterprise,
I'm placing you under arrest.
Mr. Worf?
Admiral, if you
will come with me.
Captain...
I'll have to be
placed under arrest as well.
Admiral.
I have a lot
of friends
at Starfleet
Command, Captain.
You're going to need them.
♪♪
I've spoken with
fleet Admiral Shanthi.
There will be a full inquiry
once we reach Starbase 247
and that will probably lead
to a general court-martial
of Admiral Pressman
and several others
at Starfleet Intelligence.
Your involvement
in this affair
is going to be thoroughly
investigated, Will.
There'll be some hard
questions for you to answer.
I understand.
You made a mistake
12 years ago
but your service
since then
has earned you
a great deal of respect
but this incident could cost
you some of that respect.
I can't help but feel
that I should have
come forward
a long time ago.
But when the moment came
to make a decision
you made the right one.
You chose to tell the truth
and face the consequences.
As long as you can
still do that
then you deserve
to wear that uniform.
And I will still be proud
to have you
as my first officer.
♪♪