Captain's Log,
Stardate 47423.9:
We have arrived
at Boraal II
in response to
an emergency distress call
from Lieutenant Worf's foster
brother, Nikolai Rozhenko.
He has been stationed on the
planet as a cultural observer.
Analysis, Mr. Data.
The planet's atmosphere
is dissipating, sir.
Intense plasmonic reactions
are destroying it.
The stratosphere is
already breaking down.
There are turbulent
radiation storms
across much of
its surface.
I estimate that the planet
will be uninhabitable
in less than 38 hours.
The distress call
came in only four days ago.
Why would Dr. Rozhenko
have waited
so long
before sending it?
Atmospheric dissipation
is a rare and essentially
unpredictable event.
When it occurs,
it proceeds rapidly.
Dr. Rozhenko may not have
had sufficient warning.
What was that?
The dissipation effect
is generating
plasmonic energy bursts.
Is there any danger
to the ship?
I do not believe so.
However, we may experience
intermittent system failures
and power surges
as a result.
Keep an eye on it.
Mr. Worf, any luck?
There is still no response
to our hails, sir.
I'm attempting to scan
the observation post.
He could be hurt.
Maybe he can't respond.
WORF: Sensor interference
is significant,
but the post appears
to be intact.
Their power grid
is still functioning.
However, I am reading no
life-forms within the structure.
It's not like him
to leave the post.
Especially under
these circumstances.
Captain, I'm detecting
faint power emissions
from a system of caverns
near the post.
It could be
a deflector shield.
They can't be native
to the planet.
The Boraalans
don't have anything close
to that level
of technology.
Captain, request permission
to lead an away team.
Very well.
But regardless of this
planet's immediate situation,
we must observe
the Prime Directive.
I want to minimize
the risk of contact
with the inhabitants.
You will go down alone,
Mr. Worf,
and I want to have you
surgically altered
so that you could pass
as a Boraalan.
Aye, sir.
You're worried about
Nikolai, aren't you?
Yes.
Are the two of you close?
We are brothers.
You never talk much about him.
What's he like?
Nikolai is older than I
and we are not alike.
We had many disagreements
when we were growing up.
That's not unusual.
Nikolai has
a mind of his own.
He attended
Starfleet Academy,
but he was unable
to follow the rules.
He left after one year.
But he has many
fine qualities.
He's brilliant,
persuasive...
a natural leader.
Sounds intriguing.
I look forward to meeting him.
MAN:
What are you doing here?
You're not from
our village.
Who are you?
Who is this?
My name is Worf.
I am a traveler.
How did you
survive the storms?
MAN: I would know
that voice anywhere.
Worf, is it really you?
It's good to see you.
You've changed a lot
in four years.
Nikolai?
Yes.
( laughing )
Oh, Worf.
This is my brother, Worf.
He's come to help us.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
But if you were able
to get here,
the storms
must have subsided.
Please...
Do you think it's safe enough
to return to the surface?
Please, I must speak
to my brother.
Nikolai,
what have you done?
They were dying.
I refused to sit there safe
in that observation post
and watch it happen.
I set up a deflector shield
to screen these caves
from the radiation
and then I brought them here.
What did you tell them?
They think I'm a Boraalan.
I told them I was from
another village far from here.
Well, at least you
had that much sense.
When I sent
the distress call,
I knew the Enterprise
was in this sector,
but I wasn't sure
you'd be the one to come.
I'm so glad that
you're here, Worf.
Nikolai, there is nothing
we can do for these people.
You have only postponed
their deaths.
I want to discuss that
with your captain.
And I am certain he will
want to speak with you.
Friends, my brother and I
must go back to the surface.
He has provisions and will
need help bringing them here.
We will return
shortly.
It's too dangerous.
The storms can occur
without warning.
If you're caught in one...
Don't worry. Worf is a seer.
He understands the nature
of the storms.
He'll know when
it's safe to travel.
Yes.
That is correct.
Our seer died when
the storms first came.
We've been without
his guidance for many weeks.
Let me go with you.
I know the terrain better than
anyone and I can help.
No, Vorin.
Worf and I will be safe.
We'll return shortly.
Doctor, you were fully aware
that the atmospheric dissipation
could not be stopped.
What did you hope to accomplish
by assisting these people?
I was trying to give
them a future.
What I propose is
we create an atmospheric
shield on the planet.
We can camouflage
the equipment
just as was done
with my observation post.
No one will ever
know it's there.
You can't be serious.
Indeed, I am.
I realize it will
only provide atmosphere
for a limited area
on the surface,
but it will be enough
to save one village.
I have no intention of
compounding what you have done
by committing another
gross violation of
the Prime Directive.
Captain,
the Boraalans have
a rich and beautiful culture,
a deep spiritual life.
They deserve the chance
to survive,
and isn't that
what the Prime Directive
was truly
intended to do--
to allow cultures to survive
and grow naturally?
Not exactly.
The Prime Directive
was designed
to insure noninterference.
But aren't we interfering
either way?
If we take no action,
it's a conscious decision
to let the Boraalans die.
Exactly.
We have the power
to save some of them.
All we have to do
is exercise it.
We are sworn to
uphold the principle
of the Prime Directive.
And until that is changed,
there is no further course
of action that we can take.
Is that understood?
Some of my...
log recorders are still
in my observation post.
They contain
most of my research.
Since it appears
that the only way,
I'm going to preserve
the Boraalan culture
is in a museum...
I request permission
to return to the surface
and retrieve them.
I'm afraid
that won't be possible.
But you can have full use
of the ship's computer
to set up a com link
and upload your data from here.
If there's nothing further,
you're dismissed.
I am sorry, Nikolai.
I wish there were
another way.
I am quite familiar with
your communications systems.
If you like, I will help you
set up your com link.
I'll do it myself.
Captain, atmospheric
dissipation has accelerated
over the past
several hours.
I estimate
the planet's atmosphere
will be completely gone
within three minutes.
Captain, I've completed
my data uplink.
With your permission,
I would like to integrate
my research logs with
the ship's library computer.
Of course.
DATA:
The mesosphere is gone, sir.
Plasmonic reactions
are now beginning
to break down
the troposphere.
Put it on screen.
What's going on?
It appears
the plasmonic reactions
are continuing to interfere
with our sensors.
I thought you had
compensated for that.
I had, sir.
I will attempt to engage
additional filtering elements.
Visual reestablished.
This is one
of those times...
when we must face
the ramifications
of the Prime Directive
and honor those lives
which we cannot save.
I find no honor in this
whatsoever, Captain.
You will forgive me
if I don't stay.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
Helm, take us
out of orbit.
Set a course for
Starbase 87, warp five.
HELM:
Aye, sir.
What happened?
There appears to be
an unusual power drain
in the EPS distribution net.
RIKER: What's the source?
Unknown, sir.
It is difficult
to localize.
The power drain is registered on
my security grid as well, sir.
It appears to be coming
from Deck ten.
All right, Mr. Worf,
get a security team on it.
Aye, sir.
Concentrate your scans
on the EPS transfer links.
Computer,
open Holodeck five.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Holodeck five is in use.
Override. Authorization:
Worf-theta-six-one-nine.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Holodeck control systems
have been bypassed.
NIKOLAI:
Worf, come in.
Nikolai?
What are you
doing here?
I have something
to show you.
Whatever you do,
stay quiet.
Look.
I've done what you
refused to do.
I've saved them.
NIKOLAI: I started thinking
about this days ago
when it became clear
the planet was doomed.
I knew if I could gain access
to your ship's computer,
I could generate
a replica of the caves.
The hard part was transporting
the Boraalans into the Holodeck
without anybody on
the Enterprise noticing.
But I was able
to blank out the sensors
and make it look
like interference from
the plasmonic bursts.
And it worked...
perfectly.
The Boraalans were transported
while they were sleeping.
They never knew
anything had happened.
Bridge.
It's a simple plan, really,
that's the beauty of it.
Worf, trust me.
This is going to work.
Trust you?
You never had any intention
of obeying the captain.
I wasn't going to let
those people die
just because your captain
started quoting
Federation dogma to me.
Your duty was to respect
the captain's orders
and to uphold
the Prime Directive.
Duty?
That's all that really
matters to you, isn't it?
Well, I refuse to be bound
by an abstraction.
The lives of
the people of Boraal
are far more important
to me.
You worry too much, Worf.
You always did.
Everything will work out.
You have disgraced
yourself.
And you have
disgraced me.
And I want nothing more
to do with you.
You realize your career
is finished.
I know that, Captain,
and I would do it all again.
What do you expect us
to do now?
You have left us
with a colony of Boraalans
who think they're still
on their own planet.
I didn't beam them up
without a plan.
I've given this
a lot of thought.
I think we can find
a new planet,
an M-class world
that can be their new home.
A home which would look
very different from Boraal.
You can't really believe
that they'll be fooled.
That's where
the Holodeck comes in.
I'll go back and tell
the Boraalans we're
going on a journey
to a different place where
they'll be safe from the storms.
The Holodeck can gradually
change the terrain as we travel
so that, in the end,
the Holodeck simulation
will match the conditions
on the new planet.
Then we'll simply
beam them down.
What if it doesn't work?
What if they become aware
that something strange
is going on?
Captain, I can't prepare
for every contingency,
but I assure you, I'm accustomed
to thinking on my feet.
I'll deal with
the situation as it evolves.
I'm not enthusiastic
about this plan,
but I don't see
that we have another option.
Very well,
let's give it a try.
Thank you, Captain.
There are countless
M-class planets
in Federation space
that can support the Boraalans.
We need to narrow
the parameters.
It will take approximately 9 1/2
hours to complete the analysis.
Even then, there's
no guarantee that we'll
find a suitable planet.
That is correct, sir.
Captain, you'd better
take a look at this.
What is it?
We've got a problem, sir.
I don't think
it's going to be possible
to keep this Holodeck
simulation stable.
PICARD: Why not?
LA FORGE:
The plasmonic energy bursts
from the planet are affecting
the ship's systems.
We're having problems
with the EPS systems
and the power
distribution matrix.
And as a result,
the Holodeck imaging processor
has been
severely destabilized.
It's not a question
of whether the simulation
will break down,
it's a question of when.
There's no way around it?
Not while it's running.
In order to fix it, I'd have to
shut down all of the Holodecks
and re-initialize
the entire system.
That will take hours.
We'll just have to hope the
simulation holds long enough.
Very well,
let's try it.
Mr. La Forge, I want you to
monitor the situation
very carefully and keep an open
com link with the Holodeck
so as to be apprised
of any problems.
Aye, sir.
Captain, I'll return
to the Holodeck
as soon as my surgical
alterations are completed
and I'll prepare the Boraalans
for their journey.
Considering the situation
you have put us in,
I don't think it's wise to leave
you alone with those people.
Mr. Worf will accompany you.
Sir, perhaps someone else
would be a better choice.
Counselor Troi
is familiar with...
Mr. Worf, the Boraalans
already know you.
There's no need to introduce
them to anyone new.
Aye, sir.
Keep a close eye
on your brother.
I don't want him making
this situation worse than it is.
My friends,
we have returned.
We have food.
This is difficult to say,
but you have a right to hear it.
By the time Worf and I
had reached the surface,
the village was gone.
The storms have
destroyed everything.
There is nothing left
for us to return to.
We can't survive in here.
Our supplies won't
last forever.
That's why we must leave.
There is a place far from here
where there are no storms.
It will be
a difficult journey,
but, in the end,
we will have a new home.
I know a way
through the caves.
We will travel safely
until we return to the surface.
Where is this new land?
As we said,
it is far from here.
It will not be like
the home you knew.
Even the stars
may be different.
Why would they be different?
And how do you know
we'll be safe there?
My brother is a seer.
If he says we'll be safe,
you must trust
that we will be safe.
( woman screams )
What's wrong?
Look!
Do not worry.
It is an omen.
What does it mean?
It is the sign...
of La Forge.
It is a message
to travelers.
It is said when these lines
appear and disappear
in a pool of water,
the road ahead
will be filled
with good fortune.
Hang in there, Worf.
Give me just a second...
there.
That should do it.
You see? Our journey
is already blessed.
The road ahead is long.
Let us have a meal together,
then we'll make
preparations to leave.
Worf, very good work.
Apparently, we don't make
such a bad team after all.
We are not a team.
I am here because Captain
Picard ordered me here.
Worf, don't we both
share the same goal?
Aren't we both trying
to make this plan work?
Only because you
forced us into it.
I'm not ashamed
of what I did.
I'm not sorry
I saved their lives.
You have not changed.
You still expect people to
solve the problems you create.
I'm not here to work out
the issues of our childhood.
I'm here to save a people,
who I care about,
and if that upsets you,
then so be it.
DATA:
These are the two planets which
best match our search criteria.
Draygo IV features an unusually
large temperate zone.
However, it is within three
light-years of Cardassian space.
There are constant border
disputes in that sector.
The alternative
is Vacca VI.
It is located in
the Cabral sector.
That's pretty isolated.
It offers a less
hospitable climate
than the Boraalans
are accustomed to.
However, it would still appear
to be the better choice.
Do you disagree,
Doctor?
No, Data, you're right.
It's just that the enormity
of what we're doing
is overwhelming.
We are deciding
the future of a species.
It is a formidable
responsibility.
There are so many questions
we don't have answers to.
What if the climate is so
different that it affects them
in a way that
we can't anticipate?
How do we even know
they'll be able to survive?
And if they do,
how would their society evolve
and what impact will it have
on the Vaccan system?
We have no idea
what this decision
will mean
to their future.
Doctor, I do not believe
we can offer any guarantees.
We can simply make the best
choice we have at the moment.
All right, Data.
Vacca VI it is.
Data to Bridge.
Picard here.
We have located a new home
for the Boraalans, sir.
It is Vacca VI
in the Cabral sector.
We can reach that in 42 hours
at maximum warp, sir.
Very well.
Helm, set course
for Vacca VI.
HELM: Aye, sir.
( laughing )
What is this?
Our chronicle.
The history
of our village?
Doesn't your village
keep a chronicle?
Not in this manner.
Then how do you teach your
children their history--
who their ancestors were,
where they come from?
We tell each other stories...
make up songs.
Stories change with
each person who tells them...
but this--
this will always
be the same.
Our chronicle
has been maintained
for 17 generations.
I was only able to
save the last six.
This shows the destruction
of our village.
This is you and Nikolai
leading us to safety.
We must leave.
Gather your belongings.
One of the scrolls is gone.
I must have dropped it
in the passageway.
I'll go find it.
We must stay together.
You will have
to leave it behind.
Worf, the chronicle
is the life of our village.
Without that past,
our future means nothing.
I must find it.
Go.
And return quickly.
Seer.
I am an old man.
Would you help me
with my gear?
Of course.
That is Tarrana,
my daughter.
I am fortunate
she was old enough
to survive the storms.
She is a fine girl.
Oh, she is
a beautiful girl.
She has not been
promised to anyone.
If I do not reach
our new home,
I would like her
to become your wife.
You will reach your new home.
I promise.
( buzzing )
Can I help you?
( buzz of conversation )
Are you okay?
Do you need some help?
It's okay.
Take it easy.
All right, everybody,
back off. Back off.
I know things must look
very strange to you,
but everything's going
to be all right.
No one's going
to hurt you.
We're friends
of Nikolai and Worf.
Don't be afraid.
Nikolai?
Yes.
He's my friend,
and that means you are, too.
I promise.
I won't hurt you.
Please... help me.
Where am I?
I'm sorry,
there's nothing I can do.
His neurophysiology
is very unusual.
I can't wipe his memory.
I see. How is he?
As well as can be expected.
I've given him
a mild sedative
and Troi's been
speaking with him
and he seems much calmer.
Does he understand
the situation?
I think so.
Contact Mr. Worf.
Make sure that he knows
what's going on.
TROI:
Here he is now.
This is Captain Picard.
Vorin, isn't it?
Why did you
bring us here?
Your planet was dying.
It could no longer
support life.
We took you away from it.
But...
we never left the caves.
We have the ability
to create the illusion
of other places,
like the caves
on your planet.
You've actually spent
the last two days
here on this starship,
not on Boraal.
Then our home... is gone.
Yes.
PICARD:
Vorin, listen to me.
We can visit
many other worlds.
We can take you to one
where you can build a new life.
A new life?
A chance for your culture,
your people
to survive and grow.
How can we grow
when everything that made us
who we are is gone?
Dobara,
you go on ahead.
I will carry your pack.
Go and join the others.
Thank you, seer.
It will be dark soon--
a few hours.
Would you ask
Mr. La Forge
to create a suitable
campsite for us
a few kilometers
from here?
What's wrong?
Vorin has left
the Holodeck.
How did he get out?
I do not know.
But Dr. Crusher cannot
erase his memory.
What will they do
with him?
They've explained
the situation to him.
He must make
his own decisions.
Wait.
Are you saying that
if Vorin wants to come back
in here, they'll let him?
That is right.
He is not a prisoner.
But if he comes back here
and tells the others
what he has seen
on the Enterprise,
everything we have done
will be for nothing.
Then you should have
considered that
before you beamed them
on board.
But you never think of
the consequences of your acts.
If you mean by that that
I'm willing to do something
while others hesitate,
that's true.
Everywhere you go,
you create chaos.
How many times did our parents
lie awake at night
wondering what kind of
trouble you were in?
Oh, if only I could
have been like you--
Worf, the perfect son!
I was not perfect, but I
was not wild and disobedient.
Of course not, you were
too busy doing your duty.
I would rather
be accused of that
than making
our mother weep.
But I see it is clear,
you have no intention
of changing.
I see no reason
to discuss it further.
Commander, the Holodeck
malfunctions are increasing.
I'm running every
stabilization routine I know.
WORF: How much longer
until we reach the new planet?
We'll be there in less
than eight hours.
You're just going to have
to hold things together
a little while longer.
WORF:
Someone is coming.
May I speak with you?
Yes, of course.
I don't know what
Nikolai said to you,
but please...
forgive him?
It is an old argument.
I've never seen him
like this.
He's usually so...
confident,
so sure of himself.
But now he seems...
different.
Do you know why?
No. No, I do not.
Ever since Vorin was lost,
people have been afraid--
worried that we won't
reach our new home.
We need Nikolai's strength
now more than ever.
When the storms
first came to our village,
many of us
were ready to die,
but Nikolai refused
to let us.
He gathered us together
and led us into caves.
He saved us.
He is a brave
and compassionate man
and I love him.
Please...
go to him.
Make things right
between you.
I want us to be a family.
Us?
Yes.
I want you to consider
yourself my brother.
After all...
...you're going to be
the uncle of my child.
We are in synchronous orbit
over the beam-down site, sir.
Good.
Mr. La Forge,
how much longer
before we can transport
the Boraalans?
LA FORGE:
A few more hours, Captain, but
we've got some problems here.
I don't think the Holodeck's
going to last that long.
We've had materialization errors
and resolution failures
all over the place.
And it's getting worse.
The simulation could
fall apart any minute.
We'll have the Transporter
Room standing by,
but we may have to
transport the Boraalans
whether you're
ready or not.
Please keep
Mr. Worf apprised.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
You have the Bridge,
Number One.
We still have one more
problem to worry about.
( door chimes )
Yes.
We have arrived at the planet
that I told you about.
Have you made a decision?
I believe I would like
to go back to my people.
I see.
What do you intend
to tell them?
I don't know.
If you tell them the truth,
what will happen?
Will they believe you?
( laughing )
I'm not sure.
It is a fantastic story.
Perhaps they will think
that you have had
an hallucination
or that you're insane.
I don't think I would like
to live the rest of my life
knowing what I know
and being regarded
as a madman.
On the other hand,
they may believe
your fantastic story.
They will learn about...
alien worlds, starships.
That would be disastrous.
It would destroy
everything they believed in.
I can't tell them
the truth...
but I don't think I can
live with a secret.
Then stay here.
Make a future
for yourself with us.
I need some time.
Please.
How could you have
mated with a Boraalan?
What were you thinking?!
I don't owe you
an explanation.
This is a matter
between Dobara and myself.
As usual, you are only
thinking of yourself.
And as usual, you are here to
point out the error of my ways.
You have treated
Dobara with dishonor.
I have not!
I love her and we are going to
raise our child together.
That is not possible!
I cannot allow you
to remain here.
You will have
to kill me first!
( loud crackling )
What does it mean?
The storms have returned.
We'll all be killed.
No, you won't.
Worf has the power to end
the storms once and for all.
Yes, but everyone must
take shelter in the tents.
The tents won't protect us.
Worf will protect you.
You must trust him.
Hurry, hurry.
Get to your tents now.
Commander, it might be helpful
if you could produce a storm--
wind, lightning
and thunder.
I'll see what I can do.
NIKOLAI:
Get in! Get in!
The storm
is getting worse!
Stay inside.
Worf and I will
take care of you.
Commander, energize.
The storms
will not return.
As I said he would,
my brother Worf
has saved us all.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47427.2:
The Boraalans have safely
reached the site
of what will eventually
become their new village.
None of them suspects
they ever left their planet.
However, our success
has come at a high price.
I think it was some form
of ritual suicide.
He said that he had
nowhere to go.
He would have died even if
we hadn't interfered.
But he wouldn't have
died alone...
and afraid.
Are you saying you're sorry
we saved the Boraalans?
No, of course not.
Our plan for them
worked out well.
( sighs )
But I wish that Vorin
could have bridged the gap
between our two cultures.
I would have liked the chance
to have known him better.
What?
Go inside.
Nikolai, don't.
Please.
I told you
you would have to kill me
to get me away from here.
I do not want to
fight you, Nikolai.
Things were never easy
between us, were they?
No.
It's my fault.
If I had been more like you,
we wouldn't have had
so many problems.
No.
If you had been
more like me,
these people would
not be here now.
You gave them
a chance at a new life.
And I intend to share
that life with them.
The village will need
a new chronicle.
Someone has to begin it.
My child will
need a father.
My place is here.
I'm finally taking
responsibility.
You were never
good at drawing.
How will you
keep a chronicle?
I learn quickly.
Then perhaps
there is hope.
Could I take
this with me?
Hmm... it's yours.
I will have to
explain all of this
to mother and father.
They won't understand.
They may.
I will tell them...
that you are happy.