CRUSHER:
Most of the people
on this colony
will remember
my grandmother as a healer
but her abilities
went beyond that.
She didn't just relieve pain
and fight illness.
She knew that well-being is
more than just a healthy body.
Her remedies often included
words of advice
as well as medicinal teas
and often they were
just as bitter-tasting.
I will miss Felisa Howard
very much--
her healing, her advice
and most of all the inspiration
she has provided me
throughout the years.
Rest in peace, Nana.
( murmurs of "Amen" )
And so now we commit her body
to the ground--
earth to earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust--
in sure and certain hope
that her memory will be
kept alive within us all.
MAN:
Amen.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds
to seek out new life
and new civilizations
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
That was
beautiful.
Oh, thank you.
Deanna, did you notice
a strange man at the service?
He was in his mid-30s,
with longish hair.
No.
He threw a flower
on Nana's grave-- a camellia.
It was her favorite flower.
She used to keep them
all over the house.
Maybe he was a friend
or one of her patients.
It was a very personal gesture
and he gave me
a remarkable look.
Well... I guess I should be
going back to the house.
There are some things
I need to do.
It's only
a few minutes from here.
Would you mind coming along?
I'd love to.
Thanks.
How long do you
plan on staying?
A few more hours.
Why?
Well, as you
know, Caldos
is one of the first
terraforming projects
of the Federation.
Our weather controls
and fusion systems
are nearly
a century old.
I wouldn't mind having
a starship engineer
take a look at them.
Perhaps give us
a few upgrades.
Maybe in exchange for
a tour of the colony
and a home-cooked meal?
Well, we are due
at Starbase 621
tomorrow morning
but we could delay
for a few days.
Yes, I'm sure we could
find the time.
Excellent.
I would enjoy that tour.
Caldos colony is a most
impressive accomplishment.
I actually feel as if I'm
in the Scottish Highlands.
Well, that was
the intent.
The cornerstone of
every building in town
was brought
from Edinburgh
Glasgow, Aberdeen.
The founders wanted
everyone to feel
that they had a piece
of the real thing here.
They didn't want to
just imitate Scotland--
they wanted
to re-create it.
Tell me, Governor,
I'm curious.
You're obviously
not Scot yourself.
What was it
that drew you here?
Oh, something about the
culture, the heritage.
When I was a boy
my family visited Glamis
Castle in Scotland
and as I looked out
across the Highlands
I felt as if
I had come home.
Your grandmother
had remarkable green eyes.
Every Howard woman
has had green eyes
except for my mother and me.
How well
do you remember your mother?
Very well.
I loved her very much.
I can remember...
her face smiling down at me
and I can remember
the sound of her
voice and her scent
but, mostly, I remember Nana
who raised me
after my mother died.
That's beautiful.
It's a family
heirloom.
It's been in
the Howard clan
for generations.
It's supposed
to symbolize
the enduring
Howard spirit.
"Wherever they may go-
the shining light to guide them
through their fortune."
Nana always kept it lit.
I remember sitting here,
listening to ghost stories
with only the candle burning.
You should take it with you.
I think I will.
I'm going to head back
to the ship.
You don't have to leave.
I just thought
you'd like some time alone.
I'll see you later.
Thanks.
( heavy sigh )
Who's there?
What the hell
are you doing?
Get out of my house.
I wouldn't be so high
and mighty with me
Beverly Howard Crusher.
I spent more time here
in the past five years
than you have
in the past 20.
How do you know who I am?
I'm Ned Quint.
I took care of your
grandmother's house
and her affairs.
Nana never mentioned you.
Oh, there's lots of things
she didn't talk about.
Let me get rid
of that candle.
Why?
That candle has brought
nothing but misery
and bad luck to
your grandmother.
Look, Mr. Quint, I don't know
what your relationship was
with my grandmother
but this is my house now
and these are my things.
That candle
has been a curse
on your family
for generations.
Now, if you have
a lick of sense
you'll listen to me
right now do away with it.
Now give it to me.
This is a family heirloom
and I intend to keep it!
Now would you please
get out of my house.
Now!
Howard women-- always
the same stubborn fools.
I wash my hands
of it now.
You stay on
in this house
and you keep that damned candle.
I'll not be responsible
for what happens.
Get out!
The colony's aqueduct system
is functioning normally
as are the communication relays.
We've been having
a few tremors
the last couple of months.
Could you check the
seismic stabilizers?
Certainly.
You can't imagine
what it's like
trying to enjoy
afternoon tea
while the earth
is shaking.
Governor, did you know
you had a power fluctuation
in your weather
control system?
No, our weather control's
been working perfectly
for the last 22 years.
I can't isolate
the exact source
but the fluctuation
seems to be originating
from one of the substations
that regulates
atmospheric humidity
for the colony.
Is this going
to be a problem?
No, not yet,
but power distribution patterns
are already off by five percent.
I suggest we analyze
the planet's weather patterns
to see
if they have been affected.
I am reading
unusually high humidity
across the entire
southern desert region
and there is increasing
cloud activity
above the northern
coastal area--
possibly the formation
of a storm system.
A storm?
It's the middle of summer.
We don't have rain
at this time of year.
Data, let's see
if we can correct this.
I'll check out the colony's
climatic flow array.
I will run a diagnostic
on the thermal regulators.
Don't worry, Governor.
We'll keep you dry.
I certainly hope so.
There's a caber toss scheduled
for tomorrow afternoon.
I'd hate to see it spoiled
by an unexpected downpour.
You wouldn't believe
what I've been reading about
in my grandmother's journals.
You know she had a lover.
Do you believe that?
Nana was 100 years old.
Mmm. It would seem
that the Howard women
have exceptionally
vigorous libidos.
I certainly hope so.
After all,
I hope I can find
a handsome young man
in his 30s
when I've passed
the century mark.
Thirties?
Yes. According
to these journals
his name is Ronin
and he's 34 years old.
They met just after
my great-grandmother's death
and I think I saw him
at the funeral.
A handsome young man tossed
a camellia onto her grave
but the strange thing is
she never mentioned him
in her letters, never once
and yet it appears
they spent almost all
their time together.
It's as if she led
an entire life
that I knew
nothing about.
Well, it looks as if
we're going to be on Caldos
for a few days more.
This will be
a good opportunity
for you to get your
grandmother's affairs in order.
Thank you.
Thirties?
MAN:
Beverly...
( gasping )
You dreamt you were in bed
with someone?
Not exactly.
I was in bed
but there wasn't another person
in my dream.
It was more like a presence.
You said you felt a touch.
A pair of hands.
They were moving
across my skin.
Like a caress?
Yes, and there was a voice,
a man.
He whispered my name.
It was as if I knew him
or more like he knew me.
He knew exactly
how I liked to be touched.
It was the most
physical dream
I've ever had.
The sensations were very real
and extremely arousing.
Frankly, I'm envious.
I did fall asleep reading
a particularly erotic chapter
in my grandmother's journal.
She wrote
very detailed descriptions
of her experiences
with Ronin.
Well, that's bound
to cause a dream or two.
So, shall we start going
over the personnel reports?
You know, I think he had
a ring on one of his hands
when he touched
my shoulder, my neck.
I wonder if I'll have
another dream tonight.
I'd read two chapters.
You probably want
to be alone.
I'll leave.
No, Ned. It's okay.
Look, I'm sorry we got off
to a bad start yesterday.
I've been reading
my grandmother's journals
and I know how much
you meant to her.
Aye. She was a grand lady.
You'll not see many
more like her.
You have your
grandmother's fire
that's for sure.
Ned, you're welcome
to stay at the house
after I've gone.
I need someone
to take care of the place.
That's very kind
of you, lass
but I'll ne'er set foot
in that house again
and I recommend that
you do not either.
Why?
Like I tried to tell
your grandmother
the house is haunted.
Haunted?
You believe what you want, lass.
Just do not light that candle.
Why not?
It'll bring the ghost.
It's his home.
Oh, he's out now,
wandering across the land
angry,
angry at being driven out.
That's why
he's bringing the storms.
Ned, the weather system's
control is malfunctioning.
The Enterprise
is trying to repair it.
Oh, sure, but who do you think
is causing the malfunction?
I think your imagination is...
Think what you want,
see what you want.
Just do as I say.
Do not light that candle
and do not go
to that house
or before you know it
I'll be burying another Howard
in this cemetery.
( thunder crashing )
Captain, I am detecting
atmospheric turbulence
over the colony
and large pockets
of electrical activity.
On screen.
WORF:
It is growing in intensity, sir.
That's one hell
of a thunderstorm.
Bridge to Engineering.
Mr. Data, we're reading
an extremely large storm system
over the Caldos colony.
I thought that the
weather control malfunction
was not severe.
It began as a minor
power fluctuation, sir
but the effect has spread
throughout the control grid.
It has caused
an unusual concentration
of cumulonimbus activity
above the colony.
Captain, I suggest we
set up a power transfer
between the Enterprise and
the weather substations--
try to give them enough power
to stabilize the storm.
PICARD:
Make it so.
( gasps )
( creaking )
Who's there?!
Ned?!
Is that you?
Hello!
( loud thump )
I know somebody's here,
so I suggest you...
( rattling )
( gasping )
( mirror shatters )
All right, now, that's it.
If you don't show yourself
right now
I am calling the Enterprise
and there
will be ten security guards here
within 30 seconds.
MAN ( whispering):
Beverly.
Beverly,
I've come back for you.
Who are you?
Don't you remember?
I came to you last night
while you were asleep.
No, that was a dream.
I'm calling the Enterprise.
Now do you remember me?
Yes.
What's...
what's happening to me?
Right now, I feel so strange.
I love you, Beverly
just as I loved Felisa
before you.
Are you Ronin?
Yes.
You saw me at the funeral.
Who are you?!
I am a spirit.
I don't believe in...
Ghosts?
Nor did I in the beginning.
I was born in 1647
in Glasgow on Earth.
You're telling me
that you're
an 800-year-old ghost?
I found a home
with Jessel Howard.
She was a pretty lass
with a mane of red hair
and eyes like diamonds.
Oh, I loved her very much.
When she died
I stayed with her daughter
and her daughter
and on down through the years,
generation after generation.
And now you're here on Caldos,
200 light-years away?
When your family moved out
into the galaxy
I moved with them.
I don't believe you.
I believe you are
the most beautiful women
I have ever known.
Oh, what's...
what's happening to me?
We're becoming one, Beverly.
We're going to be together.
I don't understand.
Stop it!
( door chimes )
CRUSHER:
Come in.
Hi, Bev. I just wanted
too see if you were going
to Mok'bara class
this morning.
No, I think I'm going
to skip it today.
I'm exhausted.
Did you have
another dream last night?
Not exactly.
Is anything wrong?
Not at all.
Beverly, if I didn't know
any better
I'd say you were seeing someone.
Deanna...
Now I know
you're seeing someone.
I'm not seeing anybody.
I met someone, that's all.
Well, you obviously have
romantic feelings for him.
Beverly,
when are you going
to realize
that you can't fool me?
Who is it?
All right.
I met Ronin.
Ronin?
Your grandmother's lover?
He's unlike anyone
I've ever met before.
I know this sounds
crazy, but...
I have never known
anyone who is so...
Passionate.
Exactly.
I can see why Nana
fell in love with him.
This sounds very strange,
doesn't it?
I admit it's...
unusual.
I'm very happy for you.
But I want you
to consider something.
You and Ronin have both suffered
a tremendous loss.
Very often
shared traumatic
experience
can create
the illusion of closeness...
and romance.
Well, thank you
for your concern
but I think
I know what I'm doing.
Besides, I didn't say
I was in love with him.
I'm just intrigued.
You know, Captain,
I moved to this colony
because it was a
re-creation of Scotland
but I must admit it's getting
to be a little too realistic.
( sneezing )
What the hell
is going on?
There appears to be a
condensed suspension
of water vapor
approximately
one degree Celsius.
Fog.
It just sort of rolled
in on us, sir.
There has been a malfunction
in the ship's
environmental control.
We've traced
the problem
to the power transfer beam.
There's some sort
of feedback coming
from one of the colony's
weather substations.
Another power fluctuation?
WORF:
Captain the temperature
in Ten-Forward
has dropped below freezing
and deck 13 has lost gravity.
Mr. Data, disengage
the power transfer.
I am unable to terminate
the connection, sir.
A feedback loop has formed
in the transfer beam.
I will have to go
to the substation
and attempt to correct the
problem from there.
Make it so.
In the meantime
I think I'll go
get my jacket.
DATA:
I have analyzed
the control module
in the primary
weather control grid.
It appears the station
is experiencing
a system-wide
power failure.
This is impossible.
The backup system
should have...
( loud beeping )
DATA:
Excuse me, sir.
You are dismantling
the primary
power conduit.
I must ask you
to stop.
No!
Get away from me!
You don't understand!
He's trying to kill us all!
( moans )
He is dead.
From what I can tell he was
trying to shut down
the entire
weather control system.
He was pulling out
the primary plasma conduit.
It's probably what caused
the plasma discharge
that killed him.
I knew Ned Quint.
He was an honest man.
He kept mostly to himself.
I don't know why he'd
try something like that.
Well, it's going
to take us some time
to get the system
back on line.
I'd say we need
another day at least.
In the meantime, Governor
you should expect
the weather problems
to continue.
CRUSHER:
I think you better
take a look at this.
Data, you said
there was a plasma discharge
from the console
when Quint was killed.
That is correct.
Well, that wasn't
what killed him.
I'm detecting
an anomalous
energy residual
throughout his body
right down
to the cellular level.
Whatever it is
it wasn't the result
of a plasma discharge.
Anything?
I cannot identify
the energy residual.
However, it appears to have
the same anaphasic signature
as the power fluctuations
we observed from
the weather control system.
It's possible
that whatever caused
the weather malfunctions
also killed Quint.
It is possible.
We should scan the colony
for any energy readings
that match this
anaphasic signature.
Governor, with
your permission
I'd like to take the body
back to the ship
to run further tests.
Of course, Doctor.
Ensign, ask Dr. Selar
to run a biospectral
analysis.
Yes, Doctor.
You're not going to run
the tests yourself?
No, I have some things
I need to attend to.
Ronin, I've got to talk to you.
Are you here?
I'm here.
Beverly, did you miss me?
Yes.
But I must talk to you.
There's been an accident.
I know.
Quint is dead.
Well, why did it happen?
What was he doing?
Beverly, there's
something more important
we should talk about.
Ronin, I've got to know.
Quint's dead.
Ronin.
Yes.
I need you to help me.
Help you?
It's not easy for me
to take corporeal form.
I can't do it for long.
I want you to
light the candle.
Quint said you lived
in the candle.
Is that true?
Yes, if I'm away
from it for too long
I begin to weaken.
That's why the women
in your family
have always kept
the candle lit.
The candle's on the ship.
I'll go get it.
No.
I must go with you.
How?
The power transfer beam--
I can travel along it.
Then when the candle's lit,
then what happens?
Then we'll be together...
always.
Computer, secure door.
I lit the candle.
Where are you?
Shh, shh.
It's all right.
We're together.
We're going to be one.
I'm going to become
part of you, Beverly.
Would you like that?
Oh, yes, more
than anything.
As it was with your grandmother
and your great-grandmother
and all of the Howard women
before them.
I'll take care of you
and you will feel love
as you've never felt it before.
Beverly,
what the hell is this?
I thought it was pretty
self-explanatory.
I'm leaving Starfleet.
Energize.
Belay that order.
Aye, sir.
Beverly, you can't just resign.
I can,
and I have.
I've decided to stay on Caldos
and become a healer
like my grandmother.
It's a proud
Howard tradition
and I've decided to uphold it.
Energize.
I've resigned my commission
so, unless you plan
on kidnapping me...
Beverly was attracted
to Ronin
in a very intense
and... intimate way.
I warned her that it
was all very sudden
but she didn't want
to talk about it
so I let her alone.
I sensed that she was
holding something back.
That she wasn't telling me
the whole truth.
Do you think this Ronin could be
exerting some sort
of influence over her?
That it's because of him
that she's staying?
It's possible
but she may really believe
she's in love with him.
This is a rash decision.
Ill-considered.
It's not like Beverly at all.
I agree
but she does have the right
to make that choice
even if we don't feel
it's a good one.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain, Geordi and I have
detected an energy residual
with the same
anaphasic signature
as the one we found
on Ned Quint's body.
Where?
Approximately 17 kilometers from
the center of the colony, sir.
It is coming
from the cemetery.
Data, I want you to go
down to the cemetery.
See if you can
pinpoint the source.
Aye, sir.
In the meantime
I would like to meet
with this Ronin.
( tricorders beeping )
LA FORGE:
The energy readings are coming
from this direction
but I can't get
an exact location.
I'll try narrowing
the scan field.
DATA:
The energy readings
appear to be originating
approximately two meters
below the surface.
I believe they are
concentrated
within this burial site.
I'm so glad you're here.
I can't imagine
what life was like
before I met you.
And it will only
get better.
Oh, Ronin.
I had no idea
I could feel this way.
( whispering ):
We're nearly merged now
as two candles join
to form a single light
so we will
flourish as one.
( knocking )
I love you, Beverly.
I love you.
Beverly?
Jean-Luc.
I'm sorry
I startled you.
I knocked,
but there was no answer.
The door was open.
I hope you
don't mind.
What do you want?
Well, I'd hoped to meet
your new friend Ronin.
He's not here.
Well, perhaps
I could wait
if you don't mind.
I'm really anxious to meet
this remarkable young man
who has swept away not just one,
but two of the Howard women.
Jealousy doesn't suit you,
Jean-Luc.
Have you...
have you changed
the color of your eyes?
I... I just grew tired
of the other color.
Don't you think it
suits me?
I think that
I preferred
your eyes the way
they were before.
I think I preferred you the way
you were before, Beverly.
Well, this is
the way I am now
and this is my life.
I've made my decision
and I'm not going
to change my mind
so please leave me alone.
Oh, no, there's
something's wrong here.
Now, Beverly, this
is more than just
an obsessive love affair
that has got out of hand.
Tell me, why is
it that no one
has seen this Ronin
except you?
RONIN:
All right, Captain.
Here I am.
I believe Beverly asked you
to leave her alone.
So, you're Ronin.
It's a pleasure
to meet you.
Where are you from?
Earth. Scotland.
How long have you been
on Caldos?
All that matters
is that I'm here now
and that Beverly and I
plan to be together
for the rest of our lives.
Data to Picard.
Go ahead, Data.
Captain, we have
located the source
of the energy residual.
It appears to be concentrated
within Felisa Howard's coffin.
LA FORGE:
Captain, we'd like permission
to exhume the body.
You can't do that.
Leave her alone.
Why not?
What are you afraid of?
I'm not afraid
of anything
but I cannot allow you
to desecrate her grave.
Data, ask Governor Maturin's
permission
to exhume the body.
Picard out.
I won't stand for this.
I'll go to the Governor myself.
Go on.
I wouldn't be surprised
if he doesn't know who you are.
He'll probably have
the same questions
that I do.
How did you get here?
What ship did
you come on?
Jean-Luc, leave him alone.
Why don't you answer
my questions? What ship?
I'd like to take a look
at the passenger list.
Where have you
been living here?
What's your position?
Who are your neighbors?
Come on, Beverly.
We've got to get out of here.
Jean-Luc!
RONIN:
Beverly, we must
stop the others.
They cannot exhume the body.
We can't just leave him.
He might die.
You must come.
I am your love.
I am the one
who will take care of you.
I can't just let him die.
Beverly,
come with me!
No.
No!
I'm sorry.
I'm going to stop them.
Come on, come on.
I'm all right.
Beverly, go after him.
Go to the cemetery.
La Forge to Enterprise.
We're ready down here.
Aye, sir.
I am reading definite signs
of anaphasic energy
in her body.
It appears to extend
to the cellular level.
That's impossible.
She was nowhere near
the weather station
when Quint was killed.
She died of
natural causes.
I suggest we run
a deep tissue scan
to look for
any signs of...
( groaning )
CRUSHER:
No!
Ronin, stop this.
Stop this, please.
Beverly, it's all right.
Have trust in me.
You're not Nana.
Nana's dead.
Leave her alone!
Beverly!
Forgive me.
These men were trying
to stop us
from being together.
Once they're gone
everything will be right.
No, it won't.
You've been infusing me
with the same sort
of anaphasic energy
that killed Quint.
He was trying to destroy me.
I had to defend myself.
Oh, my love.
I would never harm you.
I am here to protect you.
No, you're not.
There's no such thing
as a ghost.
You are some sort
of anaphasic
life-form.
Anaphasic energy
is extremely unstable.
It needs an organic host
in order to maintain
molecular cohesion
or else you'll die,
isn't that right?
Beverly.
I also scanned
the candle.
The flame is plasma-based.
You were using it
as a receptacle for yourself
in order
to get to me.
In order to merge with me!
You have been using me,
Nana, my entire family
for centuries!
And I loved all of them!
And they loved me.
Give me the candle, Beverly.
No, no.
Put it down...
or I will kill him.
Set it down and walk away.
No!
Crusher to Riker.
Will, close off all
the plasma conduits
in the weather
control systems.
I'll explain later.
RIKER:
Understood.
You've nowhere left to go.
Yes... I do.
Keep away from me.
( groaning )
Beverly.
I love you.
Bever...
( sobbing )
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Commander La Forge and Mr. Data
have recovered
from their exposure
to the anaphasic energy
but I'm afraid
Dr. Crusher's recovery
will be
of a more personal nature.
Somehow, he realized
that one of my ancestors
had a biochemistry
that was compatible
with his energy matrix.
I imagine that he
took on human form
and seduced her
like he did me.
I was about to be initiated
into a very unusual
relationship.
You might call it
a family tradition.
But there's a part of me
that's a little sad.
How so?
I re-read the entries
in my grandmother's journals.
Whatever else he might
have done
he made her very happy.