Fletcher has more experience
with propulsion systems.
But Carstairs is
better with people.
Considering this is
a supervisory position,
I'd go with her.
I guess you're right.
Didn't we just do crew
evaluation reports?
Three months ago.
Seems like three weeks.
( yawns )
Why don't we just
give everybody a promotion
and call it a night...
Commander?
Fine with me... Captain.
Could we have two coffees,
please?
( Troi laughing )
What could be
so funny?
I mean, what's so funny
about crew evaluations?
Don't worry
about it, Sam.
Can't we just try
and have a good time here?
How can I have a good time
when my career is being decided
across the room?
Come on. Think promotion.
Promotion, promotion,
promotion, promotion...
You can't really believe
that what you're doing
will influence the outcome
of your evaluation.
Promotion, promotion...
It's a time-honored
strategy, Taurik.
The Vedeks of the Janalan Order
maintain a round-the-clock chant
for the benefit
of the Bajoran people.
Considering the history
of your planet,
that doesn't exactly validate
what he's doing.
Promote me, please,
so I can make lieutenant
and have my own room.
If you are unhappy
sharing quarters with me,
then you should put in
for a new room assignment...
just in case
you're not promoted.
( chuckling )
I've been thinking
about who to promote to Ops.
The new
night duty officer?
Mm-hmm.
Lavelle is
an obvious candidate,
but I'm also considering
Ensign Sito.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
You sure about dessert?
Yes, don't tempt me.
So, are they working
on crew evaluations?
Yep.
Who are they
talking about?
It's not my place to say.
Come on, Ben.
Please.
All right, but I'm not sure
you two are going to like it.
Apparently, you two are up
for the same job.
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Lock phasers on target.
Phasers locked.
( alarm wailing )
The enemy is firing.
Helm, hard to starboard.
Hard to starboard.
Fire phasers.
Firing.
Target is destroyed.
End simulation sequence.
Secure from drill.
Alpha shift,
your response time
was seven percent slower
than the Gamma shift.
All departments, submit
drill evaluation reports
by 0900 hours.
Ensign, you'll write
that report.
Yes, sir.
What happened back there,
Ensign?
I'm sorry, sir.
When we changed course,
I had to relock phasers
before I could fire.
Next time, try letting
the locking relay float
until the actual order
to fire is given.
They may not teach that trick
at the academy, but it works.
Thank you, sir.
Lavelle.
Sir?
Resume previous
course and speed.
Aye, aye, sir.
One "aye" is sufficient,
acknowledgment, Ensign.
( door opens )
Helm, change course for the
Argaya system, maximum warp.
LAVELLE: Aye, sir.
What happened to the
rendezvous with the Clement?
I've received new
orders from Starfleet.
We'll discuss it in
the Observation Lounge.
Mr. Data, Mr. Worf.
Ensign Sito,
take over at Ops.
Yes, sir.
The Argaya system's close
to the Cardassian border.
I wonder why
we're going there.
How would you like to be
a spider under that table?
What?
A spider under the table.
Is that like a fly
on the wall?
I guess so.
You did really well
during the drill.
Well, apparently
Commander Riker didn't think so.
I swear,
he's got it in for me.
You're imagining things.
Yeah?
Then how come you're sitting
in that chair instead of me?
I guess he figured I needed
more practice than you do.
Excuse me, sir.
Do you have a minute?
Sure, Taurik.
What is it?
I'd like you to take
a look at something.
Have you been
improvising again, Ensign?
In a manner
of speaking.
I'm running
a computer simulation
to test a new warp-field
configuration.
You got a problem here.
Your plasma flow to
the nacelles is out of sync.
Actually, sir,
that was done deliberately.
As you can see,
this configuration
has increased overall
warp-field integrity
by seven percent.
You're right.
Dr. Nils Diaz
has been experimenting
with this technique at the
Tanaline Propulsion Laboratory.
Yeah, I'm familiar
with his work,
but I never heard
anything about this.
His findings have not
been released yet.
I was able to review
a preliminary report
when I was
at the academy.
I look forward
to reading it.
I predict that when these
findings are made public,
they will become a new model
for warp-field operations.
Sounds interesting.
With your
permission, sir,
I'd like to begin tests
to see if the technique
can be adapted
to our warp drive.
There might be variables
that you didn't account for.
I was quite thorough.
I'm sure you were,
but I'd still need
to see your simulation
before I authorize any tests.
As you wish.
If you have any other ideas
for increasing efficiency,
don't hesitate
to run them by me.
As a matter of fact,
sir, I do.
When would be a good time
to discuss them?
I'll get back to you on that.
Hmm.
( clearing throat )
Excuse me, Doctor.
If you're wondering
about the evaluations,
things couldn't be better.
Actually,
I just wanted to tell you
that Ensign Reilly's condition
is showing improvement,
but thank you.
In fact, I'm recommending you
for a promotion.
How does "Lieutenant
Alyssa Ogawa" sound?
It sounds wonderful.
I'll talk to Commander Riker,
and I'm sure it'll be official
as soon as the current
crew evaluations are over.
Oh, Alyssa...
how are things going between
you and Lieutenant Powell?
Fine... I think.
You think?
I'm sure it's nothing,
but he seems
preoccupied lately.
Last night,
he had to cancel our date.
I see.
He's been putting together
a research proposal.
He's been
really busy with it.
Well, I know what
that's like.
Sometimes I get so busy
with research, I forget to eat.
I just wonder...
What? Sit down.
I've never met
anyone like Andrew.
It's as though we've known
each other forever.
You do seem very well suited.
But...
I know that in
the beginning of a romance,
it's possible to be
a little blind.
I'm not sure
I know what you mean.
Well... canceling
a date like that...
the way he's been
so distant lately...
Doctor, do you think
those could be warning signs
that he's losing interest?
Alyssa, I think
you're overreacting.
Maybe so.
If I cared about someone as much
as you care about Andrew,
he'd have to do a lot more
than cancel a date
before I'd get suspicious.
You're right.
I'm sure that
when this research is over,
things will be back
just the way they were.
Except, of course,
that he'll have to deal
with Lieutenant Ogawa.
Hmm.
I only filled in at Ops
for a half hour,
but I had to degauss
the main deflector dish,
recalibrate
the navigation grid
and use internal sensors
to find a lost puppy.
Ops is a very different
challenge from Tactical.
I can't figure out why
I'm even being considered
for this assignment.
I'm a security officer.
I recommended you.
I'll try not to
let you down, sir.
What could they
be talking about?
Have you ever considered
learning to lip-read?
You think Worf's
chewing her out?
No, he always
looks like that.
Maybe he's giving her pointers
on how to land the Ops position.
Hi, Will.
Ben. How you doing?
You call him Will?
BEN: Why not?
He's second-in-command
of this ship, that's why not.
I'm not Starfleet--
I'm a civilian.
When he's in here, he wants
to be treated like a civilian.
Riker? I bet he sleeps
in his uniform.
BEN: You only think that
because he's your C.O.
If you got to know him...
Right.
He's convinced Commander Riker
doesn't like him.
Why? Did you crash the ship
into something?
No, he just doesn't like me.
He doesn't even know you.
That's right.
You should go talk to him.
About what?
Perhaps something
you have in common.
He likes jazz, poker,
he's Canadian...
Yeah?
My grandfather
was from Canada.
BEN:
There you go.
Hi.
Excuse me.
I got to go talk to somebody.
Good evening, sir.
Lavelle.
Something I can
do for you?
No, sir, I just came
to get another drink.
Is there something wrong
with that one?
No. Actually, I...
what are you having?
Trakian ale.
Good choice.
I'll have one, too.
My grandfather
was Canadian, you know.
Really?
Aren't you one, too?
A grandfather?
No. Canadian, sir,
Canadian.
No, I grew up in Alaska.
Oh.
Well... they both...
get a lot of snow.
Yeah.
It was good
talking to you, sir.
Yeah.
Your ale, Ensign...
We're holding position
in the Argaya system.
Anything?
No, sir.
I detect no vessels
in the vicinity.
How close to the Cardassian
border are we?
Less than
5,000 kilometers, sir.
Sir,
I'm detecting an object
five meters in length.
It appears to be
an escape pod.
They must have been forced
to abandon the ship.
How far inside
Cardassian space is it?
WORF:
50,000 kilometers.
How the hell are we going
to get it out of there?
Sir, the pod's life-support
system is failing.
RIKER:
Notify, Dr. Crusher.
PICARD: Can we get within
transporter range
without crossing
into Cardassian territory?
We would need to
boost the gain
in the confinement beam
by at least seven percent.
Mr. La Forge?
I'm on it, Captain.
There, try that.
The pod is still
too far away.
Okay, I'm going to try
augmenting the frequency spread.
Bioreadings indicate
passengers humanoid.
Attempting life-form
identification.
No one told you
to do that, Ensign.
Let's just get them
aboard safely.
There, that should do it.
Confinement beam's
at 109% of normal.
Transporter Room, you should be
able to get a lock now.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
PICARD:
Dr. Crusher, are you ready?
Stand by.
Alyssa, I'm afraid I'm going to
have to ask you to leave now.
All right, Doctor.
Transporter Room, go ahead.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
What are you doing here?
I'm not supposed
to let anyone
but the senior officers
inside Sick Bay.
Do you have any idea
what's going on?
No. Do you?
I better go.
Ensign.
Sir.
( door opens, closes )
1200 hours.
Alpha shift is relieved.
Excuse me, sir.
If you don't mind, I'd like
to stay on for another shift.
I could use the training.
Now's not the best time.
Yes, sir.
Ensign, you're with me.
Bridge.
You are a certified
pilot, Ensign?
Yes, sir.
How long have you served on
board the Enterprise, Ensign?
Seven months, sir.
I understand that
you've been recommended
for the Ops position.
Do you think
you're up to it?
I do, sir.
I'm not so sure.
I'm concerned about your record.
Sir?
The incident that you were
involved in at the academy.
With all due respect,
that was three years ago.
My record since then...
It doesn't matter
how long ago it was, Ensign.
Would you do something
like that again?
I can assure you, sir,
that I would never,
never jeopardize lives
by participating in...
In a daredevil stunt?
I would certainly hope not.
But what concerns me is that
you participated in a cover-up
that impeded
an official investigation
into the death of a cadet.
Sir, I know I should have
told the truth
right from the start...
Yes, you should,
but you didn't.
Instead, you joined
with the others
to pretend that that
was simply an accident.
Now, what do you think that
tells me about your character?
Sir, if you had any idea
what it was like
after that incident...
I didn't have any friends.
I didn't have anyone
to talk to.
I had to take my flight test
with the instructor
because no one else
would be my partner.
In a lot of ways,
it would have been easier
to just walk away,
but I didn't.
I stuck with it.
Doesn't that say something
about my character, too?
Well, I'm really very sorry
you didn't enjoy your time
at the academy, Ensign.
As far as I'm concerned,
you should have been expelled
for what you did.
Quite frankly,
I don't know
how you made it
on board this ship.
You're dismissed.
Another two seconds...
Okay, that's enough.
Sir, I'm a little puzzled.
Why are we intentionally
damaging the shuttlecraft?
We're evaluating
hull resiliency.
Starfleet requires
periodic testing.
I see.
I don't believe I'm familiar
with that requirement.
Probably because you're
not a senior officer.
If you wish,
I can reconfigure the phaser
to fire a low-intensity burst
that would not harm
the shuttle's hull.
The test procedure
would not be affected.
It's fine
just the way it is.
Now, give me another burst,
about four seconds...
right here.
Do you want me to fire
from this position?
Actually, why don't you
do it from over here?
That would be consistent.
Consistent with what?
With making it appear
that this shuttle
had fled an attack.
What makes you think
that's what we're doing?
The pattern of fire
you have asked for
is similar to
what might result
if the shuttle
had fled an attacker
while engaging
in evasive maneuvers.
It's an amazing coincidence.
Yes, sir, it is indeed.
Shall we proceed
with the testing?
Yes, Ensign.
Thank you.
Alyssa, thank you for
coming so quickly.
We have to prepare
for surgery.
We have a comatose patient
with a subdural hematoma.
Yes, sir.
I want to make it clear
that you are not to discuss
what you see here
with anyone.
I understand.
We'll need to synthesize
at least a liter
of Cardassian blood.
It's your bet, Taurik.
What I can't understand is
why we're just sitting here
so close to
the Cardassian border.
It must have something to do
with that escape pod
we picked up.
Don't you think, Sito?
Maybe.
I wonder who was in it.
You know what I heard?
It was Ambassador Spock.
That is most unlikely.
BEN:
That's what I was told.
By whom?
I can't say.
They beamed whoever was in it
straight to Sick Bay.
Did you see anything
when you were down there?
No.
Dr. Crusher just asked me
to help her
with the laboratory schedule.
I thought Lieutenant Powell
was going to join us tonight.
He had to do a double shift.
That's too bad.
He must be the worst
poker player I've ever met.
It's your bet, Sam.
Twenty.
The thing is, I saw Powell in
Ten-Forward with another woman,
and the way they were
talking, it made me wonder.
Well, if he's seeing someone
else, he should tell Alyssa.
I mean,
it might hurt her now,
but it would be better
in the long run.
I've been meaning to talk to
you about something, Mr. Worf.
I don't think Ensign Sito's
prepared for the Ops position.
Well, I must say
I disagree, sir.
Counselor,
pair of fours bets.
I'm listening.
BEN:
The bet is 50.
It would be illogical
for the captain
to deny you a promotion
for something you did
as a cadet.
He said it shows
I don't have character.
What did you say?
What could I say?
Maybe he's right.
Hey, you're
a damn fine officer
and you deserve that post
as much as anyone.
One thing's for sure,
I won't be getting it.
Not if it's up to Riker.
Well, it is
your decision, sir,
but I am certain
if you give Ensign Sito
a chance to prove herself,
she will not disappoint you.
Very well, I'll take her
under consideration.
Besides, I'm not
convinced about Lavelle.
Really? Why?
He's too eager to please.
He's always trying
to ingratiate himself to me.
Why assume he's doing that
to get the job?
Fifty.
Here's your 50,
and 100 more.
TROI:
I don't know.
It seems to me that you
and Lavelle are a lot alike.
What?!
We're not at all alike.
You're bluffing.
You think so?
Yes, and I'm not going
to let you
get away with it.
You know, Sam,
maybe you shouldn't
try so hard with Riker.
It doesn't matter
whether he likes you,
as long as he respects you.
And he must, otherwise
he would not be considering you
for the Ops position.
You're probably right.
Maybe I'm just telling myself
that he hates me
so that if I don't get promoted,
I'll have an excuse.
You in or not?
At this juncture,
the odds of my winning this hand
are less than 39 to one.
I fold.
Commander's flush
is still working.
No help, Worf.
( Worf groans )
Ooh, tens and deuces
for the Doctor,
and jacks and fours
for the Counselor.
Ah, three sixes.
Fold.
Looks like it's just
you and me.
You going to go another 50?
I'm thinking.
Give me a second here.
Didn't you tell me
that you took up poker
so you could be in the
officer's game at the Potemkin?
I happen to like poker.
But your senior officers
might have thought
that you were trying
to ingratiate yourself.
I guess it's lucky
that they realized
that you were young
and inexperienced
and decided not to hold it
against you.
Hmm.
Maybe I have been
a little hard on Lavelle.
I do not believe
he is bluffing.
I do.
Here you go.
What have you got?
Flush.
I cannot believe this!
I am your worst nightmare.
BEN:
I knew it.
How could you tell
I was bluffing?
You don't really expect me
to answer that, do you?
Look, it's getting late.
Maybe we should
all get some sleep.
One more hand.
Mm-mm.
Come on, Geordi,
you don't have to quit
just because I'm unbeatable.
No, there's something I need
to do down in Engineering.
I'll get you next time.
I'll be there.
Good night, everybody.
TROI AND DR. CRUSHER:
Good night.
Bye.
OGAWA: See you later.
What I find curious is that
when Commander La Forge saw
that the technique I was using
was actually more efficient,
he seemed annoyed.
Of course he was.
He didn't like the fact that
you knew something he didn't.
Do you think that I have
irreparably damaged
my relationship with him?
Well, it depends
on what kind of a guy he is.
BEN:
Ante up, gentlemen.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Commander...
As you were.
I dropped by to see Taurik.
What can I do
for you, sir?
Well, I'm headed
for Engineering
to run those tests
on the nacelles.
Since you've already put in
some work on the technique,
I thought you might like
to give me a hand.
I'd be pleased to, sir.
Great. Let's go.
How about some blackjack?
I've got to get some sleep,
so I can be sharp tomorrow.
Why? So you can get promoted,
have more responsibility
and have to get to sleep
even earlier?
Good night.
Come in.
DR. CRUSHER:
Ben, what are you doing here?
I just cleaned out
some junior officers
and I thought
I'd do the same here.
You're welcome
to give it a try.
Pull up a chair.
BEN: Thanks.
Dismissed.
Ensign Sito.
Yes, sir.
I also teach
an advanced class.
I believe you may be
ready to participate.
However, before
you can join the group,
you must pass
the Gik'tal.
Gik'tal?
Yes.
It is a very ancient
Klingon ritual.
It tests your knowledge
of the forms of the mok'bara.
I should practice first.
No.
No practice.
That is part of the ritual.
The test must be
unannounced.
Can you see?
No.
Good.
The Gik'tal has begun.
Defend yourself!
You must anticipate
my attack.
Yes, sir.
Defend yourself!
( groans )
Are you listening, Ensign?
Yes, but...
Defend yourself.
Ow!
You did not anticipate.
How am I supposed
to defend myself
when I can't see a thing?
Stop making excuses.
Replace the blindfold.
No!
It's not a fair test.
Very good, Ensign.
You have passed
the challenge.
What? By taking off
the blindfold?
It takes courage to say
the test is unfair.
One thing
I don't understand.
Doesn't Gik'tal mean
"to the death"?
You speak Klingon.
Sir...
is there really such a thing
as a Gik'tal challenge?
No, there is not,
but perhaps next time
you are judged unfairly,
it will not take so many
bruises for you to protest.
All I've ever wanted
is to make a career for
myself in Starfleet.
I can't change what happened
at the academy-- no one can.
All I can do is work hard
and try to earn the respect
of the people
I serve with.
If you're not going to
give me that chance,
then I respectfully request
that you transfer me
to another ship.
If you're looking
for a more lenient commander,
I don't think
you'll find one.
Permission to speak
freely, sir?
Please do.
If you didn't want me
on your ship,
you should have said so
when I was assigned to it.
It's not your place
to punish me for what I did
at the academy.
I've worked hard here.
My record is exemplary.
If you're going to judge me,
judge me for what I am now.
Very well, Ensign, I will.
It took courage
to come here and face me
after what I said
to you the other day.
I didn't ask you here
because I was assessing
your qualifications
for the Ops position.
I don't understand, sir.
I was harsh with you
because I wanted to assess you
for a very
important mission--
a mission that could
put you in a situation
that would be far more
unnerving than a dressing down
by your commanding officer.
Can I ask what
that mission is, sir?
Join the senior officers
in the Observation
Lounge at 0900 hours.
We'll discuss it then.
Yes, sir.
And, Ensign...
I do know why you ended up
on the Enterprise.
I asked for you.
I wanted to make
sure that you got
a fair chance
to redeem yourself.
Thank you, sir.
You wanted
to see me, Doctor?
Yes.
Alyssa,
I think you know
how much I've come
to depend upon you here.
I've recommended
your promotion
because your performance
here has been exemplary.
Thank you, Doctor.
I appreciate that.
But more than that...
I've come to
think of you as a friend,
someone I really
care about.
It's nice of you
to say that.
I feel the same way.
So...
you and Andrew Powell...?
Someone told you.
Told me what?
We were going
to keep it a secret
until the promotions
are announced.
A secret?
He asked me to marry him.
Alyssa, that's wonderful.
I'm so relieved...
I mean happy.
Please.
Take a seat, Ensign.
This is Joret Dal.
He was in the escape pod
that we retrieved.
He is a member of
the Cardassian military
and a Federation operative.
He has risked his life
to bring us
invaluable information
about Cardassian
strategic intentions.
Information that could
very well
enhance the security
of Bajor,
as well as other planets
in this sector.
Now, it is
absolutely imperative
that we return him safely
to Cardassian space.
It will not be easy.
The border is
heavily guarded.
Since his ship was destroyed,
he'll be using one
of our shuttles.
If a patrol stops me,
I will claim to have stolen it.
We have distressed
the shuttle
so that it appears
to have been fired upon.
Joret will attempt to talk
his way past the patrol.
If I were alone, the chances
of my succeeding would be slim,
but if I had
a prisoner with me,
a Bajoran terrorist,
I would appear to
be a bounty hunter.
Border crossings of that
nature are not uncommon.
And for a price,
the patrol can be convinced
to look the other way.
Once the shuttle
is safely past the patrol,
Joret will put you
into an escape pod
and return you back
across the border.
Since the pod is so small,
it will be difficult to detect.
We'll be waiting here
to pick you up.
I understand, sir.
Ensign, this is obviously
a very dangerous mission.
I am not ordering you
to take part in it.
Then I volunteer, sir.
Be certain you understand
the risk you are taking.
If you are captured...
I'm Bajoran.
No one knows better than I do
what Cardassians do
to their prisoners.
I've made my decision.
Very well, Ensign.
Will you report to Sick Bay?
Dr. Crusher will explain.
And, Ensign Sito,
I must ask you
not to discuss
this mission with anyone.
Yes, sir.
I didn't realize
she would be so young.
( door opens )
The captain
asked Dr. Crusher
to make it look like
Joret had mistreated me.
We're all set here.
Sir?
I just want you to know
that I really appreciate
the fact that you've always
had confidence in me.
Good luck.
I'll see you soon.
We're approaching
the border.
It won't be long
before we're detected
by the patrol ships.
When they stop us,
do you want me to say anything?
No, it should seem
that I've broken your will.
If you're asked
any questions,
look at me as though
you're afraid to answer.
Can I ask you something?
Why are you doing this--
risking your life
for Starfleet?
I don't consider
myself a traitor
if that's what you're asking.
All my life,
I've served in the military.
Once, it was an institution
dedicated to the security
of Cardassia.
Now, it's little more
than a platform
for ambitious guls
hoping to make their
reputations in battle.
If the information
I've provided
helps Starfleet deter
even one pointless skirmish,
I've served my purpose.
I'm sick of war.
My people need peace.
I never thought
I'd hear a Cardassian
say something like that.
And I never thought
a Bajoran would risk her life
to help a Cardassian
get home.
( beeping )
A patrol ship's moving in
on our position.
We don't have
much time.
She must have left
on that shuttle.
There's no other
explanation.
Do you have any idea
where it went?
Toward Cardassian space.
That's what
I'm worried about.
Oh, there was
one other thing--
I noticed the shuttle
was damaged...
Sam, can we talk
about something else?
Well, don't you care
what's happened to her?
Of course.
But we have to accept the fact
that we're not always told
about everything
that happens aboard ship.
Well, we can at least tell
each other what we know.
Wait a minute.
Do you two know something?
Sam, please.
Oh, I can't believe this.
We're friends!
We're also
Starfleet officers.
I'm not allowed
to talk about it.
Okay.
I understand.
I better get going.
I got duty
in a half an hour.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47566.7:
We have reached the coordinates
in Federation space
where Ensign Sito's
escape pod
was to have
rendezvoused with us.
However, we have been
waiting for over 30 hours,
and as yet,
there is no sign of her.
Report.
We've completed a long-range
scan of the area, sir.
The escape pod doesn't
seem to be out there.
It is possible
that at this distance,
we are unable
to distinguish the pod
from the inorganic matter
normally present in space.
Try narrowing
the scan field.
See if you can pick up
any biosigns.
Sir, it would help if I knew
what kind of life signs
to look for.
You're scanning
for Bajoran life signs.
Yes, sir.
Nothing yet.
The pod is 32 hours overdue.
Sir, I recommend
we launch a probe
to increase the range
of our sensor sweeps.
Launching a probe
into Cardassian space
would be
a treaty violation.
Mr. Worf,
prepare a probe
and launch when ready.
Aye, sir.
WORF:
Probe launched, sir.
( console beeping )
Sir, I am detecting
signs of debris
200,000 kilometers
inside Cardassian space.
Its mass and composition
indicate
it could be the remains
of a Federation escape pod.
Captain's Log,
supplemental:
We have intercepted
a Cardassian report
stating that a Bajoran
prisoner escaped her captor
and was killed
in an evacuation pod
as she tried to leave
Cardassian space.
( bosun's whistle sounds )
To all Starfleet personnel,
this is the Captain.
It is my sad duty
to inform you
that a member of the crew,
Ensign Sito Jaxa,
has been lost
in the line of duty.
She was the finest example
of a Starfleet officer
and a young woman
of remarkable courage
and strength of character.
Her loss will be deeply felt
by all who knew her.
Picard out.
You okay?
Uh-huh.
( sighs )
LAVELLE:
I just got promoted.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
It just doesn't feel right.
For all I know,
she was going to get
the promotion instead of me.
You shouldn't
feel that way, Sam.
She would have been
happy for you, Sam.
The best way to remember her
would be to excel
in your new position.
We're proud of you, Sam.
Excuse me, sir, but I need
to move this table.
What?
There's an empty seat
over there.
I appreciate
what you are trying to do,
but it is not appropriate.
You were her friends.
I was only
her commanding officer.
Sir, I happen to know that
she considered you a friend.