Bridge Officer's Log,
Stardate 47611.2.
Dr. Beverly Crusher reporting.
We have rendezvoused with
Counselor Troi's shuttlecraft.
She has just returned
from a three-day class reunion
on Starbase 231.
Send a message to commander Data
and inform him of our delay.
Aye, sir.
Deanna, welcome back.
Thank you.
I was just reporting in.
I didn't expect to find
anyone up except Data.
Data's away on assignment.
A Federation deep space probe
went off course
and crashed on Barkon IV.
Some of the material
in the casing was radioactive,
so Data was sent
to recover it before it could
contaminate the biosphere.
Isn't Barkon IV inhabited?
Yes, it's
a preindustrial society,
but the probe crashed
over a hundred kilometers
from the nearest settlement,
so Data shouldn't
have any contact
with the Barkonians.
So... how was the reunion?
Fine-- it was good to
see some old friends.
I'd lost touch
with most of them.
It's interesting to see
the different paths
some of their
lives have taken.
Beverly, you
don't usually stand
a watch on the Bridge
even when Data's
not here.
I volunteered tonight.
I like to put in a little
Bridge time now and then--
stay on top of operations,
tactical procedures.
The truth is, I like it.
It's not every doctor
who gets to command a starship,
even if it is the night shift.
May I ask you
a personal question?
Mm-hmm.
Why did you decide
to become a commander?
I mean, you don't
need the rank
in order to be
chief medical officer,
so why put yourself
through all
the extra work?
Oh, I don't know.
I never even thought
about my rank for a long time.
It seemed pretty trivial
compared to being a doctor
but then about eight years ago
I started to feel like I wanted
to stretch myself a little.
Commander,
there's no response from
Commander Data to our signal.
Continue sending him updates
on our schedule.
MAN: Aye, sir.
Is something wrong?
No, I just wanted
to let Data know
there'd be a delay
in picking him up
for a few days.
We have orders to rendezvous
with the Lexington
and take some medical supplies
to the Taranko colony.
But he's not responding.
Geordi said that the radiation
from the probe
might interfere
with communications.
I just thought I'd try anyway.
MAN: So, when you return
from school tonight,
I'll be meeting with
the village elders.
GIRL: Again?
Gia...
I know, I know-- you're
the town magistrate
and you have a lot
of work to do.
But it always seems
like you're in some
kind of meeting or...
( electronic noise )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
( electronic muttering )
Gia, go home, now.
Who are you?
What do you want?
( speaking very slowly ):
Wha...
you... want.
What...
do you want?
What's wrong with you?
What's...
wrong with you?
There's nothing wrong with me.
Who are you?
What is your name?
Can you understand me?
My name is Garvin.
My name...
is Garvin.
( giggles )
I thought I told you to go home.
I know.
I...
do not know my name.
What?
You asked...
if I knew my name.
I do not.
Well, at least
you seem to be
understanding a little more.
Yes.
It is...
becoming easier.
Ask him where
he's from, Father.
Gia, go on to school.
I'll deal with the stranger.
Yes, Father.
Good-bye.
Your eyes and your skin
look so strange.
Your clothes.
You look like you've been
in some kind of accident.
I do not remember...
being in an accident.
What do you remember?
I walked here...
from the mountains.
The mountains?
The mountains are over
200 seltons from here.
I have a clear memory
of my journey.
What do you remember
before that?
I have no prior memory.
Do you know what that is?
No.
May I?
May I have it?
Yes.
There might be something in here
that can tell us who you are.
I wonder what
these markings mean.
Radioactive.
What?
That is what is written
on the container.
You can read this language?
Evidently.
Radioactive.
What does that mean?
I do not know.
Perhaps it is my name.
I've never heard
a name like that.
You must come
from a very distant place.
( playing up-tempo jazz )
( playing two short
questioning notes )
Is that supposed
to be a question?
( playing affirmative note )
Because if you're
asking me
if I liked what you
were playing
then the answer's yes.
( playing a "thank you" )
You know, this is
a much better way
of communicating for you.
It's far less confusing
than the way you normally speak.
( playing a sour note )
I knew I could count
on my imzadi--
the ship's counselor--
to boost my self-image.
I'm glad to be of service.
Did you come here for
something in particular
or just general
Riker-bashing?
Actually, I wanted
to ask your opinion
about something.
I've been thinking about taking
the Bridge officer's test
and becoming a full commander.
What brought this up?
A lot of things--
working on the personnel
review last month,
talking to Beverly
about her experiences,
going to my class reunion.
Ah...
the class reunion.
You saw a few old friends
who had already taken the test?
All right, I admit,
it was a catalyst
but I can honestly say
that I've been thinking
about this off and on
for the past two years.
Why the past two years?
Do you remember
when the Enterprise
hit that quantum filament
and I was in command
on the Bridge?
I do.
Well, when that happened,
I was overwhelmed,
but then when it was over
I realized that a part
of me missed it--
not the actual disaster--
but the experience
of being in command.
I felt like I was exploring
a whole new side of myself--
not that I want to give up
counseling, by any means,
but I really would like
to stretch myself a little.
Deanna... if you take
the Bridge officer's test,
you'll have
my complete support.
But as First Officer,
I'll be the one judging
your performance,
and you should know
I am a pretty tough judge.
And I'm a pretty good student.
We'll start
tomorrow morning.
0800 hours.
Remarkable set of teeth.
Breath smells like...
Well, it doesn't have
any smell, actually.
You can close
your mouth.
Let's see...
heartbeat sounds
a little odd
but seems very regular.
Skin feels... clammy.
But you say
you feel fine?
That is correct.
No headaches, palpitations,
sluggishness, indigestion?
No. But I cannot
have indigestion
since I have not eaten.
Ah, malnutrition.
You should try
to eat something
that will build your strength
and return your vitality.
Lots of meat, butter, cheese.
That should be a start.
What about his eyes
and his skin?
They're so odd.
WOMAN:
Quite so.
I'm sure my grandmother would
have called our friend here
a demon or a spirit
or some sort of monster,
but current scientific
methodology allows us
to dismiss such
ridiculous superstitions
and concentrate
on scientific reality.
Then what do you believe I am?
You are an iceman.
Ice-man?
Yes, you probably come
from a race of people
who lived in the snow and the
ice of the Vellorian mountains.
Your skin and eye coloration
are a result
of prolonged exposure
to harsh
winter conditions.
Then I am not ill?
Well, aside from
your memory loss,
you do not seem to have
any symptoms of any illness
that I am familiar with.
No, you are an iceman.
Now, get something to eat
and a good night's rest
and I will come back tomorrow
and see if your memory
has begun to return.
( knocking on door )
Thank you.
Hello, Gia.
Hello.
What did Talar
say about him?
Is he sick?
Not exactly.
She said
he's lost his memory
but seems
to be fine otherwise.
Talar thinks
he's from a race
that lives
in the mountains.
I am an iceman.
We'll have to call you
something besides "iceman"
until your memory returns.
What was the word
on the container?
DATA: Radioactive.
Mr. Radioactive?
GIA:
I don't like
that name.
Let's call him... Jayden.
What do you think of that?
Jayden.
That is acceptable.
Right now, we need
to clean him up
and get him
something decent to wear.
Run upstairs and get some
of my old clothes for him.
Yes, Father.
I wonder if Skoran can tell us
something about
this metal of yours.
( children laughing,
indistinct conversation )
( metallic clanging )
You, Iceman,
where did you find this?
I do not know.
I told you,
he's lost his memory.
And we're calling him
Jayden for now.
Jayden, huh?
The metal is
slightly warm.
GARVIN:
All the fragments
are like that.
It's obviously been
tempered and milled--
the lustrous quality
of the metal is so pure.
This wasn't made in any forge
that I've ever seen.
Will you sell them?
You want them?
The metal is malleable enough
to make some jewelry.
They belong
to Jayden.
Do you want
to sell them?
You're going
to need money.
You may be right.
But I do not wish
to sell all the fragments.
They may provide
a clue to my identity.
I'll give you 20 doraks
for half the lot.
Agreed.
( cracking, tools clanging )
Ow! Ow!
My leg! My leg!
Get it off!
Get it off! Ow!
We need a lever!
It'll be all right.
Don't struggle.
It will...
Jayden... put it down.
I believe that the support
structure on the anvil collapsed
because some of
the wood had rotted.
( crowd chattering )
Did I do something wrong,
Garvin?
No.
Just unexpected.
It's perfectly
understandable.
Your people probably
all have great strength.
It would allow them
to fight off
the ferocious creatures
that live in
the Vellorian mountains.
You have told me
that no one from the village
has ever been
to the Vellorian mountains.
How can you be certain
there are ferocious
creatures there?
It's a well-known fact.
DATA:
But no one has
actually seen one?
Well, not to my knowledge,
but...
Father, are
you all right?
I've been tired
since this afternoon.
I'm sure it's nothing.
You feel slightly warm.
TALAR: Some fresh air
and a brisk walk
will do you good.
That sounds
like a good idea.
I'll be back soon.
You didn't like it?
I neither liked it
nor disliked it.
I simply had no appetite.
Father's cooking
isn't as good as mother's.
He tries, though.
Where is your mother?
She died about a year ago.
Father said she...
she went
to a beautiful place
where everything
is peaceful
and everyone
loves each other
and no one
ever gets sick.
Do you think there's really
a place like that?
Yes.
I do.
We just lost contact
with everything above Deck 21,
including the Bridge.
WORF:
There's something
wrong with one of
the antimatter
containment units.
The magnetic field is
starting to fluctuate.
Switch to auxiliary control.
Auxiliary control
is not on line.
We are starting
to lose containment
on antimatter
storage unit three.
All right.
Switch the EM power inverter
to the lateral...
No, wait!
Use the neodyne relay!
Commander, the neodyne relay
isn't holding.
Containment failure
in ten seconds.
Computer, emergency procedure.
Eject antimatter
storage unit three.
Authorization:
Troi-omega-omega-three-one.
COMPUTER: Unable to comply.
All power to ejection systems
has been terminated
and cannot be restored.
LA FORGE: Commander,
the unit's beginning to...
Congratulations.
You just destroyed
the Enterprise.
Thank you for
the encouragement.
Don't feel bad.
You passed everything else.
Diplomatic law,
First Contact procedure,
Bridge operations.
The engineering qualification
is one of the toughest
parts of the test.
So what did I do wrong?
I'm afraid
I can't tell you that.
Why not?
What kind of a test is this?
It's the kind of a test
that you're going to have
to take again if you want
to be a Bridge officer.
Only next time, the problem
won't be so easy.
So I suggest
you study up
on your emergency procedures.
Well, how do I know
what to study
if you won't tell me
what I did wrong?
I don't know.
I'm afraid I can't
tell you that either.
Rock, fire, sky and water
are the basic elements
of the universe.
They can be found
in every object,
every animal, every person--
everything.
The rock in this wood
can be felt
by its weight
and hardness.
If we expose the wood
to flame
we can encourage
the fire within the wood
to show itself.
We can also see smoke...
which is a part
of the sky.
The water in wood
is difficult to see.
Sometimes the elements
are buried deep
within the objects,
but the four elements
are always there.
( clearing throat )
Yes, Jayden.
I do not believe
that is correct.
Oh?
I believe you
are reasoning by analogy--
classifying objects
and phenomena
according to
superficial observation
rather than
empirical evidence.
Wood, for example,
does not contain fire
simply because
it is combustible.
Nor does it contain rock
simply because
it is heavy.
Wood, like any
complex organic form,
is composed of thousands of
different chemical compounds,
none of which is fire.
That will be enough
for now, Jayden.
As I told you earlier,
our friend Jayden here
has lost much of his memory,
so I wouldn't put too much
faith in any of his ideas.
Now, that will be all
for today.
I will see you all tomorrow.
Be sure to practice
your spelling
and arithmetic tonight.
Are you all right?
Yes, but I do not agree
with Talar's assessment.
Although I do have
gaps in my memory...
I know that fire
is not an element.
GARVIN:
That is not
what you promised me.
You're getting old,
Garvin.
I offered you 15 for the metal,
and I've given it to you.
No more.
We agreed on 20!
Garvin is correct.
You agreed on 20.
Stay out of this, Iceman.
Your memory is not
very reliable.
Father... Father,
what's wrong?
I don't know.
I feel very weak
suddenly.
You have a fever.
We should get him home.
What's wrong with him?
I suspect he...
I don't know.
I've never encountered
anything like this before.
These lesions
look like burn marks.
The fluids of his body
have overheated.
That would explain the fever
and the burning skin.
Keep him cool.
Let plenty of fresh air
into the house,
and I want you
to give him these herbs.
That will bring
his fluidic temperature down
and allow this to pass.
I understand.
With an increased
focal length
and an achromatic
objective lens,
this instrument will have
a higher effective
magnification.
I will come back tomorrow
and check on you.
( weakly )
Thank you.
Garvin...
with your permission,
I would like to begin
my own investigation
regarding the cause
of your illness.
Go ahead.
Gia, I would like you
to accompany me to the village.
I will need
some supplies.
What are you going to do
with all this?
I will use these materials
to make the laboratory equipment
I need to research
your father's illness.
Do you think
you can help him?
I do not know.
First, I must isolate
the cause of the illness...
SKORAN: There he is!
It's his fault.
None of us were sick
before he came to the village.
MEN:
True!
( angry muttering )
Am I to understand
Garvin's illness has spread?
That's right,
and you're the cause!
That's not true!
Gia, I think
we should leave.
That's it! Leave!
Get out of here!
Go back to where
you came from!
( angry shouting )
Jayden, what
are you doing?
I am studying skin samples
from Gia and Garvin
in an attempt to isolate
the cause of the illness.
Gia?
Yes.
She is also beginning to show
signs of the illness.
What is that?
It is a magnifying device based
on your hand-held instrument.
I have refined the design
to increase
the magnification level.
May I?
Of course.
How strong
is the magnification?
Objects appear approximately
500 times their normal size.
As you can see,
the cellular damage
is quite extensive.
However, based
on interstitial
transparency
and membrane
integrity
I do not believe
it is an infection
or any other form
of communicable disease.
I see.
At the moment, I am looking for
a common event or experience
that Gia, Garvin,
and Skoran may have shared
that could have
a causal relationship
to their illness.
Well, they've all lived here
in the village for many years.
I'm sure they have
many common experiences.
Yes, but since the illness
struck all three
in a relatively
short period of time,
it is reasonable to assume
the experience is recent
and unusual.
Actually, Jayden,
encountering you
has been the most
unusual experience
they've all
shared recently.
I am aware of that.
Excuse me.
I am also open
to the possibility
that I may in some way
be the causal factor.
However, since you have had
a great deal of contact with me
and you show no signs
of the sickness,
I tend to discount myself
as a likely candidate.
Still, it has to be
more than just a coincidence
that, shortly
after you arrived,
people started
to become ill.
I agree.
Jayden...
I tried to give
Father his broth,
but he won't eat.
You have a fever.
You should be in bed.
No, I'm all right.
Father needs me.
Talar is correct.
You should rest.
I will attend
to your father.
Gia...
when did you begin wearing
that pendant?
Two days ago.
Father bought it from Skoran.
Why?
May I see it?
This is one
of the metal fragments
I sold to Skoran.
( sighs )
The secondary plasma vent...
has a triple-redundant bypass...
which means that
the primary access junction
is routed through...
( door chimes )
Come in.
...would be routed through
the port transducer
matrix.
Come to give me
more encouragement?
No.
I'm actually here to tell you
that I've decided to cancel
the rest of your test.
What?!
I'm canceling the test.
May I ask why?
You've taken the engineering
qualification three times.
You're no closer to passing.
Well then I'll take it
four times
or 14 times,
or however many times
is necessary for me
to get it right!
Deanna, this is
nothing personal.
Not everyone is cut out
to be a Bridge officer.
I don't think
this is for you.
Why? Because I'm not the most
technically-minded person
on the ship?
I may have trouble
telling the difference between
a plasma conduit
and an phase inducer,
but there's more to being
a Bridge officer
than memorizing
technical manuals!
That's right,
there is.
You could spend
the next month memorizing
all the technical manuals
in the computer.
I still don't think
you'd pass the test.
Tell me one thing.
Is there a solution,
or is this simply a test
of my ability to handle
a no-win situation?
There is a solution.
Then give me time to find it.
I can't.
As much as I care
about you,
my first duty is to the ship.
I cannot let any Bridge officer
serve who's not qualified.
I'm sorry.
( sighs )
"My first duty
is to the ship..."
( whispers ):
The ship.
Computer,
load Bridge officer's test
engineering qualification,
section one.
COMPUTER: Computer ready.
Run program.
The control system for
the primary containment field
is not functioning.
Something severed
the ODN conduit
between here and
the antimatter storage deck.
Geordi...
could you repair
the ODN conduit
if you went
into the crawl space?
Sir, that crawlway is
in a warp-plasma shaft.
He would never survive
the radiation.
I know that.
Geordi, could you
repair the conduit?
Yeah. I think I could.
Then do it.
That's an order.
RIKER:
End simulation.
Something told me
you wouldn't let this go.
Congratulations.
You passed.
That's what this
was all about, wasn't it?
To see if I'd order someone
to their death.
That's right.
I knew that was part
of being in command,
and I thought
I'd prepared for it,
but, when the moment came,
I hesitated.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe I'm not
cut out for this.
You did exactly
what you had to do.
You considered
all your options.
You tried every
alternative,
and then you made
the hard choice.
Come on.
Let's get out
of here, Commander.
I have coated
this piece of cloth
with the liquid which
is used in lamps.
As you can see, the cloth
becomes luminescent when it is
exposed to an energy source.
This pendant also appears
to be an energy source.
But... where is this pattern
of light coming from?
I believe a stream
of particles is emanating
from the metallic pendant
and hitting the cloth.
I don't see any particles
coming from the pendant.
DATA:
You will see there are.
I can even block them.
It would appear
that this container
was constructed
of a material
which absorbs
or blocks
the particles coming
from the metal.
It's a trick.
No...
It is empirical data.
I believe the fragments
were originally placed
in this container
to protect people
from accidental exposure.
The word "radioactive"
may be a warning
about the dangerous nature
of the metal.
All right, let's say for
the moment that you are right--
that there are invisible
particles coming from the metal.
What should we do?
I will continue my experiment.
I would like you to gather
all of the pieces of metal
in the village
and place them
in this container.
All right, but when I return
I want a more thorough
explanation of all this...
and I want to examine
your data in detail.
Of course.
( pounding on door )
There you are!
You are the cause
of this, Iceman.
If you are referring
to the illness,
you are partially correct.
However, it is
more complex than that.
The metal fragment which...
( grunts )
What... what are you?
I do not know.
I saw it with my own eyes.
He's not a person.
He's some kind
of creature.
It's not true, Father.
We must find him...
and stop him,
before he kills us all.
I don't... not Jayden.
He wouldn't try to hurt us.
Ahh...
Come on!
( angry muttering )
Let him rest for now.
You should
rest as well.
Exerting yourself
will only make you sicker.
I'll be back.
( whispering ):
Gia.
Jayden...
Everyone's looking
for you.
Skoran said...
you're some kind of...
creature.
I do not know...
what I am.
But I am not like you.
I know...
you're an iceman.
We talked about that.
No.
I am not.
Jayden...
Why are you wearing
that hood?
I do not wish
to frighten you.
I won't be afraid.
Take it off.
Please, I have to see.
I understand your reaction.
But I do not wish
to harm you.
You or Garvin
or anyone else.
I only wish to help.
To find a cure
for the illness.
I was very close.
I must continue my work,
but it will take time.
How long until Skoran
and the others return?
I don't know.
They're looking for you now.
Then I must hurry.
Gia.
I believe
I found the answer.
Y-You found a cure?
I believe so.
I tested this medicine
on skin samples
from your father.
They showed improvement, so
I administered this to him.
He is now recovering.
What ki...
What kind of medicine
is it?
A compound I made
which will neutralize
the particles
that are making you ill.
Swallow this.
I must administer this
to everyone in the village.
But I do not think
they will trust me
after what happened
to Skoran.
I... I could tell them.
I am afraid they will not
believe you, either.
Gia... is the well
in the town square
the only source of water
for the village?
Well?
This is very
important.
Are there any other sources of
fresh water near the village?
No...
th-the nearest river...
two days away.
Then I will put this compound
into the well water.
It may be diluted,
but it should still have
enough potency to work.
Compound...
SKORAN:
There he is!
You see?
It's just as I said.
I only wish to help.
This is how
you've helped us?
By bringing this plague?
Tried to kill us all?
Well, you won't
succeed.
I won't let you!
( grunting )
Excuse me.
We're looking
for a friend of ours.
He might have wandered
into your village
a few days ago.
You'd remember him.
He would have appeared
very strange.
Pale skin, gold eyes.
He was your friend?
Yes. Do you know him?
Where is he?
I don't understand.
We didn't know his real name,
so we called him Jayden.
Are you saying he's dead?
They killed him
because they were afraid of him.
But he saved us all
from the sickness.
The sickness?
There were these...
pieces of metal.
They made everyone sick.
But Jayden put something
in the water,
and now
everyone's better.
What happened
to these pieces of metal?
We buried them
in the forest.
What was his real name?
Data.
He was my friend, too.
( beeping )
It's Data, all right.
He's buried about
two meters down.
He's been deactivated,
so I can't tell
how bad the damage is.
We could beam him and
the probe fragments
right onto the ship.
No one would know.
DR. CRUSHER:
Positronic net on line.
Subprocessor relays in place
and neuroelectrical
systems enabled.
Data, are you
all right?
I do not know.
I am surprised
to find myself here.
I thought
I was on Barkon IV.
What's the last
thing you remember?
I had located the crashed
Federation probe
and collected
the radioactive fragments.
I was attempting
to download the sensor logs
from the probe's
on-board computer
when there was a power surge.
I believe the surge
overloaded my positronic matrix.
After that...
I have no memory
until this moment.
But it appears
I had an interesting time.
RIKER:
We don't know much about
what happened, either.
Apparently, you saved
an entire village
from radiation poisoning.
And you were a very special
friend to a little girl.
Well...
if you'll excuse me, um...
I have the Bridge this watch.
Counselor, have you been
promoted in my absence?
That's right.
Which means, from now on,
you can call me "sir."
Yes, sir.