That's very good.
Well, that's
very nice.
No, it isn't.
I just can't get it right.
You think the wings
are too big?
TROI: Oh, no,
not at all.
Birds have wings of
all sizes, Eric.
And you shouldn't worry
about making it look perfect.
But Mrs. Narsu said we should
try to make our sculptures
as realistic as possible.
Well, she's right.
It is important that you
be able to make the clay
take the shape
you want it to have.
But you're not supposed
to be concentrating
on technique today.
I'm here to help you focus
on the feelings you want to
convey with your sculpture.
For instance, what do you think
about when you see a bird?
Flying?
Fine.
So, make your sculpture
make me think of flying, too.
How's it going, Data?
I have finished.
The dimensions are
accurate to within 1.3%
I'm sure they are.
Data, you obviously don't have
a problem with realism,
but you're here to
work on your imagination.
Maybe you should try something
a little more... abstract.
Here...
I want you to start
a new piece.
I'd like you to
sculpt... music.
Counselor, music is a collection
of acoustic vibrations.
How can I reproduce
a sound with clay?
Well, think of the effects
that sounds have on people.
The images that music
brings to your mind.
And then, give it a form.
It's a start.
Riker to Data,
please report to the Bridge.
Acknowledged, sir.
On my way.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47615.2.
We have encountered
a rogue comet in sector 1156.
It is not native
to this region of space
and there is no previous record
of this object
on any Federation charts.
Based on its
present trajectory,
the comet appears
to have originated
in the D'Arsay system.
That's over two sectors away.
That is correct, sir.
This object has been en route
for 87 million years.
That's a long time
alone in the dark.
Mmm.
Begin a full sensor
analysis, Mr. Data,
and log the findings
with the Federation
Astrophysical Survey.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
The comet's outer shell
is composed
primarily of gaseous
hydrogen and helium
surrounding an icy mantle.
The inner core consists
of heavier elements.
What was that?
There is a distortion
within the comet's inner core.
I believe we experienced
an intense sensor echo.
Can you correct for it?
I am attempting
to do so now, sir.
I have compensated
for the effect.
Sensors are reconfigured
for a low intensity sweep.
We are still picking up
some interference,
but the distortion
is manageable.
At these settings,
the scan will be complete
in 39 hours.
Worf says he's gonna teach us
some mok'bara
throwing techniques today.
TROI: More like
falling techniques.
Last time we did that,
I was sore for a week.
What's this?
I have no idea.
I've never seen it before.
Maybe Will left it for you--
a little present.
It's not quite
his style.
Then maybe it's a
secret admirer.
Ooh--
that's an interesting thought.
Well, you'll figure
it out later.
Come on, we're
gonna be late.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
That's nice.
Data...
This is amazing.
How did you come up with this?
DATA: I followed your
advice, Counselor.
I used my imagination.
That's an understatement.
For some reason,
as I was shaping the clay,
the image of the mask was
exceptionally clear in my mind.
The design seemed to flow
quite naturally.
Data, have you been
in my quarters?
No, Counselor.
Someone left an
object in my room.
Some kind of artifact.
And it has something
very similar to this.
And you don't know
anything about it?
I do not.
ERIC:
Excuse me, Counselor.
Can you help me
with my terminal?
It's not working right.
Perhaps we should investigate
this matter further.
RIKER: These symbols
don't match anything
in the Federation
linguistics banks.
Some kind of
alien information
has been downloaded into
our computer core.
I don't know
how it's working,
but it's reconfiguring
our systems.
How did it get in?
I was able to trace its
path from the replicators
to the sensor array.
The sensors?
They've been scanning that comet
for the past 18 hours.
Those energy readings
from the comet's core--
that sensor echo--
we still don't know
what's inside
that thing.
Maybe it's about time
we find out.
Could we use the phasers
to melt down
the shell of the comet?
Yeah. A dispersed wide-field
beam might do the trick.
And it wouldn't take long
to come up with the
firing parameters.
What do you think, Data?
Data... what's wrong?
I believe I recognize
these symbols.
How?
I do not know.
You think maybe your
systems have been affected?
It is a possibility.
I do not believe my systems
are currently impaired,
but I will run a full
diagnostic to make certain.
What do you
think they mean?
Boundary.
Border.
Road.
Companion.
Message.
Messenger.
LA FORGE:
What's that one?
Death.
Captain, phasers are
set for wide dispersal.
10% maximum power.
The beam will
automatically terminate
once the comet's
core is reached.
Very well, Mr. Worf.
Fire.
Phasers have
terminated.
Mr. Data,
what are we looking at?
Is it a ship?
I do not know, sir.
The object is nearly solid.
It is composed primarily
of fortanium and several
unknown materials.
It is over 87 million years old.
That's older than
the comet itself.
Could someone from the D'Arsay
system have built it?
There are no technologically
advanced cultures
in that system now.
But perhaps...
87 million years ago,
there were.
Why would they want to
hide something like that
inside a comet?
Possibly... it accumulated
those frozen gasses
over time as it
traveled through space.
In any case,
it's definitely responsible
for the system anomalies
we've been experiencing.
They're using our sensor
beam as a carrier wave
to transmit information into
our computers and replicators.
But the question remains, why?
What is its purpose?
Captain, I believe this object
is an informational
archive.
Why do you say that, Mr. Data?
I do not know.
However, I seem to have
an intuitive understanding
of its function.
LA FORGE:
Data, the internal structure
of that thing
is pretty complex.
And it's got a repetitive
node configuration,
which might suggest
a database of some kind,
but it could be
practically anything.
I don't see how you can know
for sure what it is.
Data, do you believe
that you're in communication
with that object?
It is a possibility, sir.
I recommend we run a
level-1 diagnostic
of my positronic net to
determine if that is the case.
Very well.
Mr. La Forge, give him a hand.
Aye, sir.
You think it's just trying
to make contact with us?
Yes, it's possible,
but if that is an archive
from some ancient
civilization,
we should allow
it to do so.
But we must be careful.
Mr. Worf, will you keep
an eye on the sensors?
If the ship is in any danger,
I want you to sever
the connection immediately.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain?
Yes, come in, Number One.
We've confined the
system corruption.
It won't be spreading
any further.
But we still have
alien symbols
floating around
in our computer.
This is quite a collection
you've assembled.
I've seen these things
all over the ship.
They all look the same--
primitive and
nonfunctional.
Ah, ceremonial,
and deceptively primitive.
Only an advanced
technological society
could have built
that object out there.
These artifacts played
a ritualistic role
in that society, I think.
Do you think
Data could be right?
Could we have stumbled across
some sort of alien library?
Oh, yes, it's possible,
and if so,
this is a find of the
most enormous significance.
That library seems designed
to do so much more
than simply
store information.
Who knows what we might
not learn from this?
I keep seeing this design.
Yes, this symbol seems to be
of particular significance.
What do you think it means?
Well, the concept
of the four cardinal
compass directions
are quite common in many
different cultures.
The words that Data
recognized in the computer--
boundary, border, road--
they were all arranged
in this design.
Well, perhaps the artifacts
that all have this
compass symbol
belong to the same
theme-- movement--
finding a direction,
traveling a path,
crossing a boundary.
And death?
One of the symbols
was death.
Well, the ultimate
boundary.
Mm-hmm.
I've seen this symbol
everywhere too,
but much less
prominently displayed.
It's always in the background--
much smaller than the others.
RIKER: What do you
think it represents?
I have no idea.
Hmm.
Lower synaptic functions
are completely normal.
Autonomous systems
all check out.
I suggest we examine my
memory subsystem next.
All right.
( gasps )
Data, what's wrong?
I am not certain.
I am experiencing a...
curious sensation.
Well, what is it?
An impulse.
Impulse?
What kind of impulse?
I... do not know.
I'm gonna check out
your higher functions.
Geordi.
What does it feel like
when a person is
losing his mind?
Data, come on,
you're scaring me.
Now, what's going on?
I do not know.
I... am different.
Well, you're gonna
be all right.
You're with me, okay?
Okay.
Listen, I'm gonna
disconnect you.
( crackling electronic whir )
What's going on?
Data...
( in high, nasal voice )
Masaka is waking.
Captain, he--
Captain!
I've been waiting
for you.
You should feel honored.
I don't usually
wait for anyone.
What is it you want?
Masaka is waking.
Are you Masaka?
I am not Masaka!
I am Ihat.
What have you done
to Commander Data?
Commander Data?
You mean the one
who was here.
Yes.
He's gone.
Who can say where?
Picard to Counselor Troi.
Report to Main Engineering
immediately.
Picard to Counselor Troi.
Report to Main Engineering
immediately.
Ihat, this place
you come from,
is it a cultural archive
of your species?
I come from Masaka City.
Are there others
like you there?
( laughing )
There are no
others like me.
( cackling )
Who is Masaka?
You will find out.
I would like to know
Masaka, speak with her.
Do you understand pain?
Death?
That is all you need
to know of Masaka.
It is what she is.
Go.
Leave this place
before she finds you.
It can be done.
I did it.
Masaka.
( raspy voice )
I am yours.
Every part of me is yours.
We should confine
him to quarters.
This is a micrograph
of what's happened
to Data's positronic net.
Now, as near as I can tell,
these are behavioral nodes.
I've counted 14 so far.
I think the archive
is using Data
to create different people
within its culture,
much in the same way
it used our replicators
to create artifacts.
As a result, Data's
real personality
has been
completely buried.
In a sense, Data has
the android equivalent
of multiple personalities.
And the archive
hasn't stopped yet.
Data's positronic net is
still being transformed.
There's no telling how many more
personalities
might emerge.
Geordi, I want you to continue
to scan the archive
and see if you can find
some way to access it.
And in the meantime,
I'll see what I can learn
from these...
people inside Data.
I'm not going to hurt you.
( raspy voice )
Only Masaka can hurt me.
I am for her... alone.
I need to speak with Ihat.
Do you understand?
Ihat.
( gasps )
( as Ihat )
Captain.
That was a cruel joke
you played on me.
For a moment-- a brief moment--
I actually thought
that woman was Masaka.
Whoever took your place
wasn't afraid of Masaka.
He seemed eager for his fate.
Pitiful, isn't it?
You won't catch
me humiliating
myself for a woman,
even if she were a queen.
Then Masaka
is your queen.
She's a lazy creature.
She spends most
of her time sleeping.
Problem is what she does
when she's awake.
Then we should try
to keep her asleep?
( laughing )
Try to stop the sun from
climbing the sky, hmm?
Mm-mm.
Only Korgano can do that,
and he's not here.
Where is he?
( gasps )
( faint voice )
Help me. Please.
What's wrong?
I'm afraid.
Of what?
Her.
Masaka?
Her!
Picard to Bridge.
Report.
The archive just activated
some sort of tractor beam, sir.
We're not able to disengage it.
Has there been any
damage to the ship?
There was an
emergency reported
in Ten Forward--
Mr. Worf's on his way.
Captain, there's some kind
of energy pulse
coming through the tractor beam.
It's overriding
our control systems.
I'll be right there.
Don't leave me.
( whispering )
I won't leave.
Please... let go of me.
Does it hurt?
Yes.
She's gonna hurt us all.
( as Ihat )
Now, you've done it, Captain.
Masaka is awake.
( alarm wailing )
Who's this?
I'd say that
that is Masaka.
He had referred
to her as "queen",
and it's not unusual in
ceremonial cultures
to find royalty
symbolized by a sun.
TROI: You said the
personalities inside Data
were in awe of her,
even terrified?
Well, according to Data,
the sun image
is also a symbol
for death.
See, there it is again--
the same U-shaped symbol.
Small and insignificant,
almost as if it's
an afterthought.
Captain, this is incredible.
These artifacts weren't beamed
here from the archives.
The matter here in Ten Forward
has been transformed.
Into living plants?
How is that possible?
I'm not sure, but bit by bit,
this ship is being transformed.
WORF: We have been
receiving reports
from the rest
of the ship.
Part of deck 12
is now an aqueduct.
What are we being
transformed into?
I'm not sure
I wanna find out.
I don't think
we have any choice.
We must destroy that archive,
Mr. Worf.
Sir, our weapons control
systems are inoperative.
However, we could
reconfigure
a photon torpedo
for manual launch.
Make it so.
( sighs )
There's so much more here
that we could have learned.
I really regret losing
that opportunity.
Okay, I've locked in the
targeting parameters.
What's the phase
alignment now?
Less than .7%.
Good, that'll do it.
I'm setting the
yield at maximum--
Sir...
the onboard power systems
are not functioning.
Let's see what's
going on here.
( gasps )
Whoa!
Something tells me we'd
better get out of here.
Engineering to Bridge.
Emergency transport.
Two to beam out.
Maybe we'd better
talk out here.
The observation lounge
has turned into a swamp.
So... what's our status?
Well, so far, the archive
has transformed
about 20% of the ship.
We've lost main propulsion
and the weapons systems
in the process.
What about communication?
Sensors? Life-support?
We have communications
and limited
sensor control.
Life-support seems
to be unaffected.
I've analyzed the
alien plant forms.
They've developed
from biological matter
we have on the ship.
The stone, the artifacts are
made in much the same way--
extrapolating from
the ship's own alloys.
CRUSHER: Apparently,
the archive
can reorder and transform
molecular structure--
including DNA--
into anything it wants.
So, it's using
our ship, our alloys,
our DNA to
create elements
of its own culture.
But why is this happening?
What does the archive
hope to accomplish?
PICARD: Well, whatever
the intent that lies
behind its process,
I'm not gonna permit
this ship to be turned
into an alien city.
Mr. La Forge,
do you have any ideas?
Well, we still haven't
been able to cut off
that beam,
but I have managed
to access the archive by
sending an energy pulse
back along their
signal path.
If I could locate the
transformation program,
I might be able
to control it.
That's a good idea.
But I feel that the
answer lies there...
with Masaka.
We must find her,
access her.
Talk to her.
Hello.
( as old man )
Difficult... to stay warm.
It's not warm enough--
not for an old man.
Tell me about Masaka.
My... daughter.
Tell me, how can I
talk to her?
Children... grow...
forget their parents.
No...
Only Korgano can talk
to Masaka.
Korgano.
Who is that?
( as Ihat )
Well...
aren't we
the persistent one?
Ihat?
Is anyone else so charming?
Masaka is taking over
my ship.
I told you she would.
I want to
talk with her,
but I understand
that Korgano
is the only one
who can do that.
Who told you that?
An old man.
Masaka's father.
Oh, yes. Yes.
Legend has it
she chopped him up
and used his bones
to make the world.
Any wonder he doesn't like
to talk about her?
How can I find Korgano?
I don't know.
He's not chasing her
anymore.
Where has
he gone?
Stop asking me
these questions.
I was fast enough to get
away from her once.
I don't want her
to find me again.
I'll wind up on her
sacrificial slab.
Ihat, if she's looking
for a sacrifice...
she can take me.
Perhaps then, she'll stop
looking for you.
( chuckling )
Well, there's an idea.
Better you than me.
Very well.
What do we do?
You must build
Masaka's temple.
The queen's temple.
That will get
her attention.
Very well.
How do I do that?
You need the sign.
I could give it to you.
So could the old man.
But just try
getting it out of him.
Give me the sign.
If she finds out...
you can't imagine her rage.
She lets people...
die of thirst.
A terrible death.
Sometimes...
she burns them alive.
She is glorious.
Ihat, the sign.
Give it to me.
If she comes,
you will take my place?
Yes.
All right.
Quickly, give me your hand.
A line, as the
unending horizon.
A curve as...
She has found me.
Masaka, show yourself.
I will go
with you.
It seems...
I was not fast enough.
( as old man )
So hard... to stay warm.
( groans )
Are you one of my children?
I can't remember
anymore.
I need your help.
I need the sign
for the temple.
For Masaka's temple.
It won't help you.
Korgano no longer
pursues her.
Only he can stop her.
A line, as the
unending horizon.
A curve as...
A line, as the
unending horizon.
A curve...
As... the rolling
hillside.
A point...
as a distant bird.
A ray...
as the rising sun.
Thank you.
Now... come sit with me.
Tend the fire.
( faint voice )
I'm alone.
No one left to help me.
She's coming.
Are all the others dead?
Did Masaka kill them?
No.
She sent them away.
It will take them
days to die.
PICARD:
Any progress, Mr. La Forge?
I think I've found the archive's
transformation program.
Will it accept the symbol
for Masaka's temple?
I think so.
I've isolated the program's
input pathways--
their key to
accept symbols.
If I input this one,
it should initiate
the transformation program.
And create the temple?
Well, I hope so.
If this is the wrong symbol,
it might turn
the Enterprise
into a big chunk of rock.
No way to know for sure.
The question is,
can we trust a personality
from an alien archive
that seems bent
on taking us over?
Ihat risked his life
to show me that symbol.
And Masaka killed him
for doing it.
I think we have to risk it.
Captain, the entire deck has
been cleared of personnel.
We may proceed.
Commander Riker,
we're ready.
RIKER:
Understood.
Initiate transformation.
Inputting the
symbol now.
It would seem that this
is Masaka's temple.
There is
no one else here.
PICARD: Ihat said that
if we created the temple,
then it would get
her attention.
It may be some time
before she shows herself.
WORF:
How will she do that?
PICARD:
I don't know.
Captain?
Take a look at this.
This is the first time
I've seen these
two symbols paired.
That could be significant.
Look, there it is again.
And again.
And there, again.
This is obviously an
important pairing.
He isn't chasing
her anymore.
Sir?
Ihat said that someone
called Korgano
isn't chasing Masaka anymore.
And the old man said,
"He pursues her no longer."
In a sense,
the small symbol
might be seen to be
chasing Masaka.
The symbol
suggests antlers
of some kind--
uh, horns.
Maybe it is meant to
represent an animal?
Animals are worshipped
in many cultures.
That smaller symbol
could represent Korgano.
Ihat and the old man
said that Korgano
was the only one who
could control Masaka.
Many ritualistic cultures
incorporate the idea of balance
into their belief systems.
Now, Masaka is a... queen,
a powerful godlike figure.
It's not unrealistic
to believe that she might
have a counterpart--
a consort.
Look around,
see if you can see
that horn-like symbol
anywhere else.
TROI: This is the
most prominent instance
of the horn symbol
we've seen yet.
WORF: But now,
it appears as though
Masaka's sun
is chasing it.
TROI: The sun
chasing an animal?
Maybe it's
simpler than that.
Maybe their relationship
is more like...
the sun and the moon.
I see.
Masaka and Korgano
switching positions.
The sun setting,
and the moon rising.
Exactly, like two
powerful rulers
changing places in
a continual cycle.
And like the sun
and the moon,
only one of them can
be in ascendance
at any given time.
( sighs )
If we can find Korgano
in the archive and
bring him out,
then perhaps he could
force Masaka to leave.
But would we be
better off with him?
Hmm.
Ihat and the others
didn't seem to be
frightened of Korgano.
Sir?
Masaka.
Masaka...
I'm Captain
Jean-Luc Picard
of the Federation
Starship--
Go away!
Please, hear us.
Your archive
is destroying--
I do not hear you!
She will not even
listen to us.
Then we will have to
find someone to whom
she will listen.
I found it, Captain.
This is the only place
in the archive
where Korgano's
moon symbol appears
by itself, not linked
with Masaka's.
All right, Mr. La Forge,
I want you to access
the transformation program,
and when you're ready,
input the symbol.
Isn't that a
little risky?
TROI: We have no idea
what the result would be.
The symbol might
generate anything
from Korgano's temple
to Korgano himself.
In one sense, Korgano
is Masaka's nemesis.
And whatever this
symbol represents,
it could be, for us,
a means to control her.
Now, if anyone
has a better idea,
I'm very happy to
entertain it.
I've accessed
the program, Captain.
Initiate the
transformation.
Another mask.
You know, we could be going
about this all the wrong way.
This is a very
ritualistic culture--
one based on symbol
and myth.
Perhaps we should try to
confront them on those terms.
If I could somehow incorporate
myself in their ritual...
then perhaps Masaka
would listen to me.
You're going to try
to pose as Korgano?
Captain, we know so little
about this culture,
and even less
about Korgano.
How would you convince
Masaka that you're him?
Well, I'm really
not certain.
But there are similarities
between this culture and
others that I've studied.
I would imagine
I'm just going to improvise.
Mr. Worf, what's our status?
I estimate we have
less than two hours
before there is nothing left
of the ship-- at least nothing
we can recognize.
Masaka?
Korgano.
Are you surprised to see me?
I thought I had
escaped you.
You should know
that is impossible.
You are a fine hunter...
but I am
a powerful prey.
You will never catch me.
Do you want to be
the prey forever?
I thought I was alone.
I thought I would not have
to share the sky with you.
But without me,
you are not complete.
I know you so well.
You live for the
chase, as do I.
Will you not miss
being the hunter?
Pursuing me?
Forcing me
from the sky
so that you can
rise again?
You know me well, Korgano.
I think...
that you are beginning
to tire.
It is difficult
brightening the
sky forever.
Mmm.
I am getting sleepy.
You always do that to me.
So that you can wake
with the dawn.
And begin the hunt again.
Let the hunt begin again.
I am eager for that.
As am I.
Riker to Picard.
I don't know what you did, sir,
but it looks like everything's
back to normal.
Acknowledged.
Mr. Data,
you all right?
I believe so, sir.
I am not entirely certain
what has happened.
Have I been
dreaming again?
I'm afraid that will take
some time to explain.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47618.4.
Commander La Forge has managed
to disable
the alien
transformation program.
Starfleet has dispatched
an archeological team
to study the archive further.
PICARD:
But I don't understand.
I thought all of
the alien artifacts
had disappeared from
the Enterprise.
That one was not created
by the archive, sir.
That is the clay mask
I originally made.
I have since
painted it.
A memento?
Yes, sir.
Although I am...
relieved to be rid of
those alien personalities,
in a sense, I am now... empty.
Hmm. I can imagine.
Dr. Crusher told me that
there were possibly dozens
of personalities inside you.
I suspect the number
was much greater.
My impression is that
there were thousands,
of all ages and
walks of life.
It was
a remarkable experience.
Well, Data, you never may
become fully human,
but you've had an experience
that transcends the
human condition.
You've been an
entire civilization.