( alarm wailing )
We are losing containment
in the starboard nacelle tube.
Try to get more power
to the field coils.
Aye, sir.
Mr. La Forge, report.
I can't shut down
the plasma injectors.
Somebody's locked out
the controls.
The plasma venting system
has engaged.
Two more decks.
Riker to Bridge.
We've almost reached
the nacelle tube.
PICARD:
Acknowledged.
Release the exterior
hull plate.
We may have
to jettison the core.
Aye, sir.
What happened?
He locked out
the controls.
Before we knew what was
happening, he stepped up
onto the walkway.
See if you can help shut
down the plasma flow.
I'm afraid if we try
to get any closer,
he will jump through
the force field.
Dan...? It's me.
It's Will Riker.
I was here yesterday,
remember?
I didn't want to do it.
But I saw them,
and they laughed at me.
They laughed.
Whatever happened,
we can talk about it.
I want to help.
Stay away!
I just want
to see your face.
That's all...
so we can talk.
I...
know what I have to do.
Dan, no!
I have unlocked the controls.
COMPUTER:
Shutdown procedure initiated.
There's still plasma
in the injector.
It will take time
to vent off.
Tell me what happened.
Maybe I can help.
I know what I have to do.
PICARD:
Space... the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
A few more seconds,
I could have saved his life.
Commander, you did
everything you could.
It was not your fault.
It was strange.
I felt as if he didn't even
recognize me...
even though I was with him
just the other day
when I supervised
the tube refit.
How did he seem then?
Fine.
I complimented him
on getting the refit done
faster than expected.
He was pleased
that I had noticed.
I met with him
about six weeks ago
during the crew
evaluations.
He was very positive.
He was looking forward to being
posted to the nacelle tube.
He was a good officer
with a fine career
ahead of him.
I don't understand
why he wanted...
( sighs )
In my years
as a Starfleet Captain,
I have had to notify
many parents
of the loss of loved ones,
but never before to suicide.
I would like to be able to offer
Lieutenant Kwan's parents
some explanation
of what happened
to try to help them
make sense of this.
Well, maybe he left, um...
a message of some kind
explaining why he did it.
I would like the two of you
to piece together a picture
of his last few days.
If he made any
personal logs,
it might be helpful
to look through them.
You're authorized to do so.
La Forge to Captain.
Go ahead.
I've just finished
my damage assessment.
We should be able to get
underway,
I'd say within the hour.
Mr. La Forge,
the medical situation
on Barson II has worsened.
Starfleet has
given us permission
to exceed warp speed limitations
so as to get back on schedule.
We'll be able to give you
warp eight if we need it.
Acknowledged.
Geordi...
would you agree that the
instinct for self-preservation
is shared by
most life-forms?
I'd say it's probably
the most basic instinct, Data.
That being the case,
I find it difficult
to understand
why someone would deliberately
terminate their own existence.
( sighs )
I don't know, Data.
All I can think is
that maybe Lieutenant Kwan
felt that there was
something...
wrong with his life.
Something that he felt
powerless to fix.
I believe I understand.
I have been in
a similar situation.
Really?
The first months
following my activation
were a difficult
period for me.
There were many problems
associated with
my becoming sentient.
Because your neural net
was still forming.
Mm-hmm.
As I acquired new skills,
neural pathways would form
replacing other
less complex pathways.
It was very...
disorienting.
I bet.
As my systems grew
in complexity,
it became
increasingly difficult
to integrate new pathways
into my existing
neural net.
The probability
of cascade failure grew
with each
additional pathway.
I came to the conclusion
it would be safer,
and easier,
to shut myself down
and start again.
Yeah, but if you
had done that,
you wouldn't have remembered
any of the things that
had happened to you.
In a way...
it would have been like
committing suicide.
So what did you do?
I decided against
the procedure.
I chose, instead,
to treat the problems
I was having with my systems
as challenges to overcome
rather than obstacles
to be avoided.
That's a great way
to look at it, Data.
I only wish Lieutenant
Kwan had been able
to look at his
problems the same way.
This is a Napean design.
His mother is Napean.
His father is human.
It all looks so normal.
For some reason,
I half expected
the place
to be a mess.
Yes.
It is strange
to think that someone
could have considered
ending his life
and yet give
no outward sign.
Just before he jumped,
he seemed almost... calm.
Well, he must have been
in a lot of pain
to do what he did.
It could be that the prospect
of ending the pain
felt like
a great relief.
This is Ensign
Calloway, isn't it?
Yes.
She is a medical
technician in Sick Bay.
It's always hard to lose
someone you care about,
but to lose them
like this...
We should check
his personal logs.
This is his last entry.
He made it before going
on duty this morning.
Personal Log,
Stardate 47622.1:
We finally finished the
nacelle tube refit last night.
After pulling
two double shifts in a row,
I'm really looking forward to
spending some time with Maddy.
Ensign Calloway.
That doesn't sound
like a man
who's planning
on taking his own life.
No. No, it does not.
I can't believe
he's really gone.
I keep thinking he's going to
show up and tell me
there's been some kind of
terrible misunderstanding.
I thought you might like to know
that in his personal logs,
Dan talked about you
a great deal.
He loved you very much.
If that's true...
then how could he
leave me like this?
That's what I'm trying
to find out.
I know it's hard
to talk right now,
but it would be
very helpful
if you could tell me
a few things about him.
When was the last time
you saw him?
Two nights ago.
We were planning our next
shore leave together.
Did he mention anything
that had happened recently,
anything that might
have upset him?
No, not really.
He did say something about work,
about Lieutenant Nara,
but it wasn't
anything serious.
Nara... she's his superior
in the nacelle tube.
Yes.
Dan sensed that she...
Well, that she felt
threatened by him--
that she thought
he was after her position.
Was he prone to mood swings
or depression?
No...
but he was very sensitive
to other people's moods.
He used to look at me
and know exactly
what I was feeling.
I always loved
that about him.
Well, Napeans are
partially empathetic.
He may have inherited some of
his mother's abilities.
He used to tease me
that when I met her,
I wouldn't be able
to get away with anything.
Dan and I knew each other
for over two years,
but we didn't get together
until a few months ago.
We took it slow.
We thought we had
all the time in the world.
Something must have happened
to him, Counselor--
something terrible--
because it's not like Dan
to take his own life.
I understand.
Please...
find out what it was.
Can I help you?
( gasps )
Oh, I didn't
see you there.
You're Lieutenant Nara,
aren't you?
Can I do something
for you, Counselor?
I'm investigating
Lieutenant Kwan's death.
I just wanted
to look around.
It's such a shame.
He was a good man.
Did you notice any change
in his behavior recently?
No.
I've been going over
the last few days in my mind,
trying to see if I...
if I missed
any warning signs.
It's as if something
inside him just snapped.
How was his
job performance?
Excellent.
He knew this ship better
than most people,
probably because
he helped build it
back at Utopia Planitia.
Did he get along
with his coworkers?
He was ambitious.
He came in here with
all sorts of new ideas
about how to do things--
some of them
very good ideas.
But not all?
No.
But after he settled in,
we got along fine.
Excuse me a minute.
Feel free to look around.
Where was Lieutenant
Kwan's station?
Right there.
( gasping )
Are you all right?
( gasps )
I don't know.
I don't know how
to describe it.
I was suddenly overwhelmed
by a flood of emotions--
fear, rage, panic--
and the sensations didn't seem
to be coming from any person.
They were just there
in the room.
Well, then whose
emotions were they?
I thought you said
you were alone.
I was.
I scanned the area.
I found no
anomalous readings.
How could you get an empathic
impression from an empty room?
I don't know.
Could the fact
that Lieutenant Kwan
was partially empathic
have anything to do with it?
What do you mean?
I'm not sure,
but certainly
the feelings Troi described
are consistent with suicide.
Could his death have left
some sort of empathic echo?
I don't see how,
but if I went back
to the nacelle tube,
I might get a better sense
of what I experienced.
I don't think I'd recommend
that right now.
You're showing elevated
levels of psilosynine.
Psilosynine?
It's a neurotransmitter
involved in telepathy.
The experience overwhelmed you
the first time.
I think you should wait until
your levels return to normal.
How long?
Three, maybe four hours.
This time, I want
someone with you.
I shall accompany you,
Counselor.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47623.2:
We've arrived at
Starbase 328 on schedule.
After taking aboard
medical supplies,
we will depart
for Barson II.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Worf.
Counselor.
Have you found anything
in Lieutenant Kwan's logs?
Everything I've read suggests
that he was well-adjusted
and optimistic.
It just doesn't
make any sense.
Can I get you anything?
No. No, nothing.
Yridian tea.
I've been thinking
about what happened to me
in the nacelle tube...
whether it was
an empathic echo
left by Kwan's death.
In the past, have your
empathic experiences
always involved the physical
presence of another person?
All the ones
I'm sure of, yes.
What do you mean,
"sure of"?
Well, when I was
a little girl,
my grandfather used to
tell me stories by the fire.
I would close my eyes
and listen to his mind
for hours on end.
He would tell you these
stories telepathically?
My grandfather
rarely spoke.
He said that was
for off-worlders
and people who didn't
know any better.
Now, the only time
I can remember his stories
is when I go home
and sit by the fireplace.
Sometimes,
when I'm alone there,
it's almost as if I can hear
his voice inside my head.
Yes. Yes, I, too,
have sought visions in fire.
I can't explain it,
but it feels real to me.
Just like what happened
in the nacelle tube.
There are things
we do not understand,
yet they exist nonetheless.
( sighs )
Perhaps I should let you
get some rest.
Oh, it's all right.
No. If you will excuse me,
Counselor.
I'll be right back.
Mr. Worf.
Commander.
Two Til'amin froths,
please.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant Corell seems to be
enjoying your company.
I'd like to think so.
Are you involved
with her?
I'm not sure yet.
Why, are you
interested in her?
No, no.
But, if I were,
I would, of course,
discuss the situation with you
before proceeding further.
I appreciate it,
but that really wouldn't
have been necessary.
I mean, I would never
want to come between
you and someone
you are involved with
or had ever had been
involved with.
Is there someone in particular
that you're talking about?
No.
Is there someone
in particular
you would rather I not
be involved with?
Mr. Worf, you sound like a man
who's asking his friend
if he can start
dating his sister.
No, no, I was merely...
Never mind.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you open
this door for me?
Yes, but only
for a short time.
After 90 seconds,
the plasma venting system
will engage
to prevent degradation
of the force field.
I just want
to take a quick look.
May I ask what
you're looking for?
I'm not sure.
( alarm wailing )
COMPUTER:
Warning--
plasma venting system
will engage in 90 seconds.
( sharp thud, Troi gasps )
No, no!
No, please!
Please, please!
No! Don't!
No!
( thud )
COMPUTER:
Warning--
plasma venting system
will engage in 80 seconds.
( thud )
Worf?
( woman laughing )
( murmured conversation )
( suppressing laughter )
( both laughing )
Counselor,
are you all right?
Let's get out of here.
Do you remember
anything else?
TROI:
Yes, I think I do.
There was a tool
crate on the floor.
It was labeled
"Utopia Planitia."
The shipyard where
the Enterprise was built.
Clearly, this was much more
than an empathic echo.
It seems that you were actually
seeing something that happened
in the Control Room
eight years ago.
Everyone was looking
directly at me,
but it was as though
I was seeing through
someone else's eyes.
Lieutenant Kwan
was partially empathic.
Maybe you were seeing it
through his eyes.
It's possible, but I don't see
how it could have happened.
Well, putting that on
one side for the moment,
let's assume that by some
inexplicable phenomenon,
you witnessed an event
that occurred
to Lieutenant Kwan.
Those faces that you saw--
did you recognize any of them?
I've never seen
the woman before,
or the man who was with her.
But there was
someone else there--
a man.
He was staring at me
in the most peculiar way.
I think he had reddish hair
and he did seem
familiar to me.
But it's all so hazy.
It's like trying
to remember a dream.
There was a woman
who was frightened
and then you saw her
again, laughing,
presumably at
Lieutenant Kwan.
What does it all mean?
I don't know, but something
terrible happened in that room.
I felt it.
Counselor,
I want you to look
through the personnel
files of Utopia Planitia.
See if you recognize
any of those faces.
If only I could go back
into the Control Room
without being overwhelmed
by the experience.
It might help me
remember some detail
that might be relevant.
I could give you an inhibitor
that would slow down
the brain's production
of psilosynine.
That might be able to suppress
your empathic abilities
and make the experience
more manageable.
It would take about 16 hours
to synthesize the inhibitor.
I'd like to try that.
Very well, Counselor.
( sighs )
I apologize
for being late.
The viral medicines we are
transporting to Barson II
require special
security measures
to insure they are
properly contained.
Have you found anything?
No.
There were literally
thousands of people involved
in building
the Enterprise.
Perhaps you should try to
narrow the search parameters.
I think I have.
The man who looked
familiar to me
may have served
on board the Enterprise
in the last seven years,
so I've asked the computer
to limit its search
to personnel who served
at Utopia Planitia
and on the Enterprise.
Ensign Salvatore--
he transferred
over a year ago.
Lieutenant Ziff--
she's in quantum mechanics.
That's him.
WORF:
Lieutenant Walter Pierce.
I remember now.
He came on board
about six months ago.
I think he's
in Engineering.
You were Lieutenant Kwan's
supervisor at Utopia Planitia.
That's right.
I was sorry
to hear what happened.
Did you ever spend time in
the nacelle Control Room
while it was
under construction?
I worked all over the ship.
In fact, I remember
running a power conduit
right behind this wall,
here.
TROI: Were you ever
in the nacelle room
at the same time
as Lieutenant Kwan?
It was a long time ago.
People were working
all over the place.
So you do not remember?
I'm sorry, I don't.
Do you recall if anything
unusual happened there?
How do you mean?
An altercation perhaps?
Possibly involving
Lieutenant Kwan.
No, nothing like that.
The way I remember it,
things went pretty smoothly.
What's this all about,
if you don't mind my asking?
Not at all.
When I was in the nacelle room,
I had an empathic experience.
We believe the Counselor
may have been seeing
an event that occurred
eight years ago.
And I saw you there.
Do you have any idea
why that might be?
I'm afraid I don't.
Lieutenant,
are you aware
that I can sense when
someone's telling the truth?
I've heard that.
Then, I'm sure that
if you remember anything
that might be relevant
to our investigation,
you'll contact me.
Oh, of course.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Counselor.
The strange thing is,
I couldn't read him at all.
But you implied that...
We have played poker
many times.
I've never known
you to bluff.
Well, it wouldn't be
much of a bluff
if you knew,
would it?
The fact that
I couldn't read him
suggests that he has at least
some telepathic ability.
But Pierce is human.
That's what
I don't understand.
Even though I couldn't
read his emotions,
I did feel that he was
holding something back.
I thought so,
as well.
Maybe we should
try to access
the Engineering logs
from Utopia Planitia.
We might find out
more about him.
There may be something in them
about Lieutenant Kwan, as well.
Mm-hmm.
It's going to take
about half an hour
for the transmission
to be completed.
Perhaps we should continue
this in the morning.
It is late.
Yes, and you must be tired.
A little.
So, I will say good night.
Good night.
We should get
an early start tomorrow.
I think we should.
I'll see you
in the morning.
Yes.
Hello.
Breakfast is ready.
That sounds nice,
but it can wait.
Why didn't we do this
a long time ago?
DR. CRUSHER:
Crusher to Counselor Troi.
Yes, Doctor?
I've synthesized
the inhibitor.
Please come to Sick Bay
whenever you're ready.
Acknowledged.
DR. CRUSHER:
Crusher to Lieutenant Worf.
Worf here.
DR. CRUSHER: Medical supplies
are ready to be taken
to Cargo Bay for transport.
I will be there shortly.
This should take effect
immediately.
Will it completely suppress
my empathic abilities?
It's hard to say
for sure,
but I can always increase
the dosage if it's not enough.
The Cargo Bay
will be off limits
to all but
medical personnel.
Thanks for your help, sir.
You're welcome.
Good morning.
Counselor.
Data and Geordi are already
in the nacelle tube.
Are you ready?
Yes.
CALLOWAY:
Excuse me, sir.
About the quarantine field
in the Cargo Bay,
it looks like we'll need
a second field generator.
I am needed here.
I will join you
as soon as I can.
All right.
WORF: Apparently my help
was not so good after all.
CALLOWAY:
( chuckles ) Yes, it was.
You were wonderful.
I think I know
what is wrong.
The generator
dispersion...
Counselor, are you okay?
I'm fine.
The inhibitor seems
to be working.
Have you found anything?
No, nothing unusual.
I don't remember seeing these
during my empathic experience.
Have they been here
since the ship was built?
No, they were installed
two years ago.
Geordi...
I remember seeing
a plasma conduit right there.
The main ODN line runs
right behind that panel.
It lifts out,
so you can get to it.
Kwan was working
on that conduit
the day before
he died.
Can you open it?
Sure, it'll take
just a minute.
Data.
Lieutenant Nara,
may I ask you something?
The work Lieutenant Kwan
was doing--
was it unusual in any way?
He was refitting
a field coil,
but it was probably
the first time
that particular panel's
been opened
since the ship was built.
Thank you.
( sharp thud )
No!
LA FORGE:
Counselor?
Are you all right?
Something happened
when you removed the panel.
There's something in there.
I am getting readings
that indicate organic material
embedded in this wall.
Organic?
( tool humming )
You're right.
Let me reconfigure
the emitter beam.
We might be able
to see what it is.
There.
This dosage should prevent
any further empathic flashes.
The bone fragments
are definitely human.
I sequenced
a DNA sample.
I'll see if I can match it
to Starfleet records.
Accessing Starfleet
personnel records.
I'd say these fragments
have been in the wall
about seven
or eight years.
WORF: ...your help with
the Barson medical supplies...
DR. CRUSHER:
You said something happened
when the panel was opened.
Yes.
I wonder if
these fragments
could have somehow
triggered your experience?
I'll run a resonance scan,
see if anything turns up.
Sir, I think
we've found a match.
Apparently,
the remains
are those of
an Ensign Marla Finn.
I'm trying to find
a picture of her in the records.
TROI:
That's her.
That's the woman I saw.
It says she was
reported missing
"from Utopia Planitia
on Stardate 40987.2."
Eight years ago.
But how did her body become
embedded in a bulkhead?
Maybe there was some kind
of an accident.
Or she was killed
and the murderer
hid her remains.
Something's not right.
Pull up Lieutenant Kwan's
service record.
I thought so.
He didn't arrive
at the shipyard
until six months
after Finn's death.
I couldn't have been seeing
through his eyes.
Then whose?
Well, it would have
to be someone
who was at least
partially telepathic.
Pierce.
DR. CRUSHER:
But you saw him there.
Yes, but not as clearly
as I could see everything else.
His face looked...
like that.
DR. CRUSHER:
A reflection.
So I was seeing
through his eyes.
And Finn was trying
to get away from him.
She was afraid of him.
I think it is time
we had another conversation
with Lieutenant Pierce.
Ensign Calloway...
thank you for your help.
Deck ten.
Worf, can I ask
you something?
Do you regret
what happened last night?
No. No, of course not.
Are you sure?
Because I don't want
to jeopardize our friendship.
Deanna, I do not regret
being with you.
What is wrong?
( sighs )
I'm not... feeling myself.
Maybe it's the inhibitor.
I'm so used to sensing
what people are feeling
and now I can't.
Perhaps I should talk
to Lieutenant Pierce alone.
That might be a good idea.
I will meet you
in your quarters later.
I'll be waiting for you.
Deck eight.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Security to
Counselor Troi's quarters.
SECURITY: Acknowledged.
I don't understand.
Lieutenant Worf said you wanted
to talk to me about something.
Where is he?
He said he had
to go somewhere.
Troi to Worf.
Computer,
where is Lieutenant Worf?
COMPUTER: Lieutenant Worf is
in Ensign Calloway's quarters.
( door opens )
Counselor?
Take Lieutenant Pierce to
his quarters and hold him there.
Security override.
Authorization:
Troi-delta-two-nine.
( giggling )
Stop it.
Stop it!
( gasps )
( screams )
( gasping )
( cries out )
CALLOWAY:
He's dead.
You killed him!
No!
You know what
you have to do.
( whimpering )
I know what I have to do.
COMPUTER: Warning--
What are you doing?
COMPUTER: Plasma venting system
will engage in 70 seconds.
You're alive.
You're all right.
I opened the maintenance door
at Counselor Troi's request.
Then turned to see her standing
too close to the force field.
It all seemed
so real to me.
I can't believe that
everything I experienced
happened in just
those few seconds.
It appears Counselor Troi
was correct.
Pierce was
partially telepathic.
His maternal grandmother
was born on Betazed.
What else have
you found out?
DATA:
According to Starfleet records
Pierce and the other persons
Counselor Troi identified
were killed in an accidental
plasma discharge
eight years ago.
Their bodies
were never found.
I don't believe
it was an accident.
I think Lieutenant Pierce
found out the other two
were having an affair.
He lost control
and he killed them both.
Afterwards, he probably
activated the plasma stream
and then threw
himself into it.
The plasma discharge
would have obliterated
any evidence
that it was murder.
( door opens )
I scanned behind the panel
Counselor Troi asked me to.
I didn't find
any bone fragments,
but I did find some traces
of cellular residue.
It's showing some kind
of psionic signature.
It may be that
when Lieutenant Pierce
was struck by
the plasma stream,
the subspace energy
present there
imprinted his empathic pattern
into the residue.
Kind of like
a psychic photograph.
That's what triggered
my hallucination.
My mind must have taken
elements from my own life
and then created
a situation
that, in many ways, mirrored
what happened to Pierce.
If you hadn't been there,
I would have jumped
just like he did.
Counselor.
When I pulled you
from the plasma stream,
you seemed...
surprised I was alive.
Well, actually...
in my hallucination,
you were killed.
May I ask by whom?
Well, you know what
they say, Mr. Worf.
Hell hath no fury
like a woman scorned.