So, why were you
rolling around
in Cyprion cactus?
You know Rebecca Smith?
The new
tactical officer?
We took a walk
in the arboretum.
We sat down,
we got comfortable.
Things got a little
romantic, and then
I rolled over. Ah!
Blurred vision
and dizziness,
uh, palpitations...
a stinging sensation
in the lower spine.
It's Terellian Death
Syndrome, isn't it?
I thought we agreed
you'd come to me
before checking
Starfleet medical database.
Yes, well, this time,
I'm glad I did.
Because maybe we can
stop the cellular decay
before it's too late.
Reg, you don't have
Terellian Death Syndrome.
Are you... you're sure?
I'm sure.
Then maybe it is
Symbalene blood burn.
No. No. I don't see
anything wrong with
you at all.
Wait a minute.
There is a slight imbalance
in your K-3 cell count.
My K-3s? Oh, no.
Barclay, I'm sure
it's nothing.
Look, I'll run
a microcellular scan.
We'll see.
This will take
a couple of minutes.
Nurse Baldwin, I need
that hemotoxin series
on Ensign Brooks
right away.
How's my
smallest patient doing?
I believe she
is doing well.
Her appetite has increased
by seven percent
and she is
beginning to engage
in prenatal behavior.
Oh, she is getting close.
You'll have a fresh
litter of hungry kittens
before the week is over.
Let me just run
an amniotic scan
to make sure
everything's fine...
Doctor?
And then I'll...
Doctor, my capillaries
are shrinking.
Excuse me.
Alyssa, can you take care
of Spot for a minute?
Start a preliminary
amniotic scan.
Yes, Doctor.
My intravascular
pressure...
it's going
through the roof.
You're right.
It is elevated.
You've also got heightened
electrophoretic activity.
Electrophoretic activity?
Is it serious?
Well, based on this,
I'd say you've got...
70, maybe 80 years.
80... 80 years?
Yes, Reg.
What you've got is a mild
case of Urodelean flu.
Now, it's nothing
serious. Most humans have
a natural immunity to it.
But the T cell in your DNA
that would normally
fight off the infection
is dormant.
Hmm.
So, you mean,
I have bad genes.
You have one dormant gene
out of 100,000,
and I can activate that gene
with a synthetic T cell
to let the body
fight the infection
naturally.
You should feel better
in a couple of days.
Thank you, Doctor.
I feel much, much better.
Good! Now, stay away
from medical database.
And you stay out
of the arboretum.
Everything looks
fine, Data.
You want to know the
sex of the kittens?
I have noticed that many
humans prefer not to know
in order to experience
the surprise during birth.
I believe I will preserve
the mystery until then.
I know what you
mean. I don't want
to know either.
Alyssa?
Spot's not the only
one who's going
to be a mother.
Oh, Alyssa,
that's wonderful!
How did Andrew
take the news?
Well, he was a little
shocked, but he's
getting over it.
I have spent the
past nine weeks as
an expectant parent.
I would be happy to
share my insights
with your husband.
If my experience
is any indication,
he will need all
the help he can get.
( meowing )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47653.2.
We are performing
field tests
of our new tactical systems
and weapon upgrades.
Mr. Worf is supervising
the exercises.
The next test will involve
the new photon torpedoes.
The explosive yield
has been increased by 11%,
and I have enhanced
the targeting system
for increased accuracy.
Sounds fascinating,
Mr. Worf. Please proceed.
Setting targeting
coordinates--
005 mark 317,
spread pattern delta 94.
Torpedoes armed
and loaded, sir.
Fire when ready.
Worf?
One of the torpedoes
has veered off course.
It appears to be
a malfunction in
the guidance system.
Abort and destroy.
The torpedo is
not responding.
Subspace detonator
will not engage.
Lock on phasers.
The torpedo
is out of range.
Even for your newly
improved phasers?
Maintain a sensor lock
on the torpedo, Mr. Worf.
We'll have
to go after it.
That would
be inadvisable, sir.
The asteroid field
is unusually dense.
The Enterprise is
too large to safely
navigate through it.
Then I'll take
a shuttlecraft
and retrieve it.
Mr. Data,
you're with me.
Captain, the shuttle
pilot who's on duty
is Lieutenant Hayes.
I happen to be a
reasonably qualified
pilot, Number One.
Besides, these tests
hardly require
the captain's
personal attention.
Understood.
Enjoy yourself.
Mr. Worf...
I think that you should
consider analyzing your
new guidance system.
Captain, I will need
a few minutes to attend
to a personal matter.
Me?
It is possible
that it will take
several days for
Captain Picard and me
to complete our mission.
I would prefer to have
a human present to supervise
the birthing process.
Well, I'd be honored.
Yes... ooh.
( purring )
I have noticed that you
are the only other member
of the crew whom Spot
seems to like.
Really?
That's hard to believe.
You're such
a sweet little kitty.
She is to you.
However,
there have been
several injuries
to other members
of the crew
who have attempted
to care for Spot.
So, has she, um...
picked a place?
A place?
Cats usually like to
pick a specific location
to give birth
and it's usually
dark and secluded.
And I believe...
that this is...
it.
I'm curious, sir.
Who's the father?
I am not certain.
Spot has escaped
from my quarters
on several occasions
and there are 12 male
felines on board.
I intend to run a full
DNA analysis on the
kittens once they...
Picard to Data.
Report to Shuttle Bay Two.
On my way, sir.
Good-bye, Spot.
I believe you are
in good hands.
You have nothing
to worry about, sir.
Oh!
( thump )
Problem?
I have performed
13 diagnostics
on the weapons array
and I can find
nothing wrong with
the guidance system.
I'll have Geordi run
a diagnostic on the
torpedo bay itself.
Maybe he can
find something.
Must you stand
so close to me?
Lieutenant,
are you all right?
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
No, you're not.
You've been working
for six hours straight.
You're tired.
Take a break.
But...
That's an order,
Lieutenant.
TROI:
Thanks for waiting.
Do not approach me
unannounced, especially
when I'm eating!
We were supposed
to be having lunch
together, remember?
I was hungry!
Well, I'm hungry, too.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Could I have an order
of Ongilin caviar?
Make that
a double order.
Certainly.
Caviar?
For lunch?
I'm in the mood
for something salty.
Besides, it's no stranger
than what you're eating.
Have you noticed how dry
the air is on this ship?
I wonder if the
environmental controls
are set properly.
( belching )
You're excused.
Here you go.
Mmm.
Is something wrong?
It has been
a difficult day.
The torpedo
guidance system failed.
It was my fault.
You always say that.
It was my fault!
I designed that
guidance system!
Worf, calm down.
I think you're under
more stress than
you'd like to admit.
Maybe you should
get some rest.
Perhaps you are right.
If you will excuse me!
I didn't mean right now.
( yelling )
We removed the torpedo bay's
primary guidance module
and we found a power
fluctuation in the
forward sensor cluster.
Now, we think it may be
a radial imbalance in
the phase discriminator.
Now, what we
want to do next
is run a level-4
diagnostic,
but we're going to
have to shut down
auxiliary power
to 19 decks...
Wait a minute.
Slow down.
You lost me back there.
Which sensor clusters?
The forward. It's...
it's a power fluctuation
in the converter nodes.
It's a minor adjustment.
It's minor.
It's all right here
on this diagram, Commander.
Hmm... I'll look
this over later.
Go ahead... you run
your diagnostic.
I'll inform the
other departments
about the, uh...
power systems.
( alarm sounds )
I'll check that.
He's full of
energy today.
I can't get him
to slow down.
He's been working like
that since last night.
BARCLAY:
It looks like
a plasma conduit
cut out in junction 17.
I'll go look at it.
Wait a minute, Reg,
I'll go with you.
Keep you posted.
Computer, increase
ambient temperature
by two degrees centigrade
and increase relative
humidity by ten percent.
Computer, reset
environmental controls
to standard.
Worf,
it's freezing in here.
You have already
raised the temperature
three times.
It is too hot.
Live with it.
Computer, execute
my original command.
I need a bath.
You have the Bridge.
Here we are.
Looks like a
ruptured conduit.
No problem.
I'll just bypass it.
( panting ):
Reg, wait a second here.
Take a look at these
corroded edges here.
It looks like something
has dissolved the bulkhead
and eaten right through
the conduit.
There are high levels
of cholic acid here--
enzymatic agents.
You know, I wouldn't
be surprised if that
solvent was organic.
Maybe we should run
a biospectral analysis
on the solvent.
Take a closer look.
That's a very good idea.
But first...
we should take a break.
You go ahead, sir.
I'll take care of it.
Commander, we received
a communication
from Starfleet.
They wanted to know
when they could expect
your performance analysis
of the new weapon systems.
The weapon systems?
Yes, sir.
The ones we've been testing
for the past few days?
That's right.
What should I
tell them... sir?
Tell them...
tell them
we haven't finished yet.
What are you doing here?
I had to be near you.
Computer, increase
temperature by
five degrees.
Get out of
that water now!
Leave me alone!
( screams )
Could I have
a glass of water?
It's so cold in here.
Your temperature
has dropped almost
eight degrees.
I want to run
a hypothalamic series
right away.
Doctor, we've had
three other crew members
complaining about
the temperature levels.
Some feel like
they have fevers.
Others-- they're freezing
like Counselor Troi.
Call Dr. Selar
and Dr. Hacopian.
It looks like we've
got some sort
of viral infection
going on around here.
I want to check
on Lieutenant Worf.
Worf, have you had any
unusual symptoms lately?
Headaches? Nausea?
Dizziness? Worf?
Worf, do you hear me?
I'm going to run a
full bioscan. I want
you to lie down.
Okay, we can
do this sitting up.
What is this?
Worf, how long have you
had this on your neck?
It looks like it's full
of some bioacidic compound--
almost like a venom sac.
Worf...
open your mouth.
( hissing )
( screaming )
Oh! Oh!
Get a hypospray.
Right away.
I managed to
get her into stasis
before the venom
paralyzed her.
She's going to need
reconstructive surgery,
but I think
she'll be all right.
Sir, we've analyzed
the venom
and compared it
to the acidic compound
found at junction 17
and on decks ten and 12.
They all have the same
enzymatic composition.
You're saying that Worf
is spraying this...?
Venom.
This venom
all over the ship?
I'd say so.
60 crewmen have begun
exhibiting strange
behavioral changes--
memory loss, fatigue,
headaches...
I think one thing
is clear.
There's some sort
of disease aboard
the Enterprise...
and it's spreading.
I'm having trouble
concentrating myself.
It's like
my mind keeps wandering.
I...
can't...
Commander, I've got
seven security teams
out hunting for Worf,
but for some reason,
the sensors are having
a difficult time
locking on to him.
I've called for a
level-2 security alert.
Do you think we should
go to a level-1?
I don't know.
What do you think?
I think we should.
Okay, sounds good.
Then you'll take care
of that... security thing?
Yes, sir, I will.
Okay. I'll notify
Starfleet.
I'll let them know
what's happening.
You have your orders.
Dismissed.
Computer,
send a subspace message.
Starfleet command.
Security channel.
Authorization...
Alpha-four-seven
authorization required to
activate security channel.
Computer...
Awaiting authorization.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
Commander Data and I have
recovered the stray torpedo
after a three-day search.
We are en route back
to the Enterprise.
Captain, the ship
is not at the prearranged
coordinates.
Have they been delayed?
I do not know. I am
unable to raise them
on any
communication channel.
Scan the vicinity.
See if you can find them.
I found it, sir--
two light-years away.
Set a course.
The Enterprise
appears to be adrift.
I am reading
power fluctuations
on all decks.
Life signs?
There are life signs.
However, sensor readings
are highly distorted.
I am unable to identify
specific life-forms.
Adjust
the axial stabilizers
to match the attitude
and rotation rate
of the Enterprise.
I'm going to dock
the shuttle manually.
( liquid dripping )
Main power is off-line.
All systems are in standby
or emergency mode.
There is no response
from any manned station.
Any sign of the crew?
I cannot access internal
sensors from here.
We will have to go
to the Bridge.
( distant growls and grunts )
That sounds like animals.
Yes, sir.
I am able to discern
over 300 different
vocalizations.
( screech echoing )
Look at this.
It is composed
of reptilian DNA.
I believe it is
an epidermal layer
that has been cast off
during molting.
But it seems to be...
humanoid.
Yes, sir.
I cannot explain it.
There are no species
aboard the Enterprise
that shed their skin
in this fashion.
( distant cries and calls )
Sir.
Hmm.
These are Counselor
Troi's quarters.
Can you tell
if she's inside?
No, sir.
Data, I want to have
a look in here.
Stand ready.
( liquid splashing )
Whew...
environmental settings
in these quarters
have been altered.
Data, over here.
Deanna...
What's happened to her?
Her DNA is in a state
of ribocyatic flux.
Her genetic codes
are being re-sequenced
and her cells are
mutating as a result.
At a fundamental
level, sir, she is
no longer human.
What is she?
Her respiratory tissue
has become capable
of metabolizing
both water and air
and her eyes
have developed
nictitating membranes.
I believe she is
amphibian, sir.
She has been injured.
Yes, sir.
There is Klingon DNA
in the wound.
It is saliva.
Are you saying
she's been bitten?
It would appear so.
I will need to run a full
biospectral analysis.
( sighs )
First, we've got to get
the ship under control.
Let's go to the Bridge.
His upper spinal
column has been broken
in three places.
It looks as though
he's been attacked
by an animal.
Yes, sir.
Has his DNA been
changed, as well?
Yes, sir.
However, it was
in its initial stages
when he died.
( console beeping )
Captain...
I am picking up 1,011
individual life-forms
within the ship.
All exhibit a
similar genetic flux
to the one we observed
in Counselor Troi.
So, the entire ship
has been affected.
Most of the life-forms
are scattered
throughout the ship.
However, there are several
large concentrations
in the arboretum
and the aquatic lab.
I've regained attitude
control to the ship,
but main power
is still off-line.
It looks as though the
entire power transfer grid
has been destroyed.
( thumping )
( growling )
Will?
Captain.
( grunting )
His cranial plates
have thickened by 20%.
His brain
is much smaller, sir.
I do not believe he can
comprehend our language.
Perhaps we can find
a way to communicate.
Will, can you
understand what it
is that I'm...?
( growling )
He looks almost
protohuman.
Yes, sir. His DNA
would seem to confirm
that observation.
Captain, I believe
the crew is de-evolving.
This tranquilizer
should keep him unconscious
for another seven hours.
What have you found out?
I have analyzed
Commander Riker's
DNA structure.
A synthetic T cell
has invaded his
genetic codes.
This T cell has begun
to activate his
latent introns.
Introns?
They are genetic
codes which are
normally dormant.
They are evolutionary
holdovers--
sequences of DNA
which provided
key behavioral and
physical characteristics
millions of years ago,
but are no longer
necessary.
For instance, Counselor
Troi's gill slits
and other amphibious
characteristics were
derived from introns
which still contain
amphibious codes.
So, these introns
are causing her DNA
to recombine in an
earlier configuration.
That is correct.
In her case,
the DNA has created
an amphibious life-form
which became extinct
over 50 million years ago.
And Commander Riker's
introns are changing him
into what appears
to be one of the
earlier hominids.
Yes, sir. I would say
Australopithecine.
Each of these stages
is another link in
the evolutionary chain
which stretches back
to the origins of all
life-forms on Earth.
Because introns can
include genetic material
from many different species
over millions of
years of evolution,
it is possible
that a wide variety of
transformations is
occurring among the crew.
What about those
crew members who
are not from Earth?
All humanoid life has
a similar genetic pattern.
The virus should work
on nonhuman crew members
in the same way.
They are each de-evolving
into earlier forms of life
on their homeworlds.
I feel I must
inform you, sir.
You have also been
infected by the
intron virus.
How long before
I begin to change?
According to
my calculations,
within the next 12 hours
you will begin to
exhibit the first signs
of your eventual
transformation.
And what will that be?
I believe
you will also de-evolve
into an earlier form
of primate,
possibly similar to a
lemur or pygmy marmoset.
Well...
before I begin swinging
through the ship
looking for breakfast,
we'd better find
some answers.
How do we reverse
the process?
I am uncertain.
We will need to run
several
micro-cellular scans.
However, the ship's
main computer has
been damaged.
Captain, the computer
in my quarters
has an independent
processing and
memory storage unit.
It should not
have been affected.
I suggest we start
from there.
Agreed.
( meowing )
It would appear that Spot
has had her kittens.
They sound hungry.
Yes.
I am curious as to
why Spot is not
caring for them.
( ratcheting growl )
It would seem
that the intron virus
is not limited
to humanoid life-forms.
No, sir.
( steady beeping )
PICARD:
What is it?
These kittens were born
less than 24 hours ago.
It would appear that
Spot's transformation
took place
at approximately
the same time.
So, spot was giving
birth to the kittens
at the same time that
she was changing into
a reptilian life-form.
I believe so.
For some reason,
the intron virus
was not passed on
to the kittens.
I do not know why.
If I remember my biology,
there are several
natural immune systems
that come into play
in the mother's womb
to protect the fetus
from viral infections.
That is true.
Placental barriers,
maternal antibodies
and amniotic fluids
all serve
as a filtration system.
Maybe we could
have inhibited
the intron virus
by using the
natural antibodies
in Spot's amniotic fluid.
It would take
further research,
but I believe,
to be effective on
humanoid crew members,
humanoid antibodies
would be necessary.
Then we should locate
a pregnant humanoid.
Nurse Ogawa has recently
become pregnant.
Where is she?
I have traced
her combadge signal
to deck 17,
section 21 alpha.
The arboretum.
( rumbling )
One of the warp plasma
vents has failed.
Main engineering
has been abandoned.
There is no one there
to fix the problem.
I can repair the damaged
plasma vent from here.
I'm going to check the
status of the warp core.
( yells )
Data!
What was that?
I believe it was
Lieutenant Barclay.
He appeared to be
partially transformed
into an arachnid.
A spider?
Yes, sir.
Are you all right,
Captain?
I have these
intense feelings of...
fear...
and panic.
I feel as if I were
being watched.
I can't...
I can't explain it.
You may be experiencing
the initial stages
of your transformation.
Early primates were often
prey to large carnivores.
As a result, their
instincts probably included
a heightened sense
of awareness.
In that case,
my instincts tell me
that we'd better hurry.
Captain, I have analyzed
Nurse Ogawa's embryo.
It is unaffected
by the virus.
I believe I can use
her amniotic fluid
as a template
for a retrovirus.
It would neutralize
the synthetic T cell
and reestablish the genetic
patterns of each host.
How soon can
you do that?
It will not take long to
isolate the appropriate
genetic material.
I will need to get
the Sick Bay
computer back on...
( tapping )
( thumping )
What was that?
( beeping )
It is large.
Approximately
200 kilograms.
It is heavily armored
with an exoskeleton.
Life signs appear
to be Klingon.
Worf.
( thumping continues )
( growling )
Set your phaser
on heavy stun.
We can't be certain
the stun setting
will have
any effect on him.
A higher setting
might kill him.
( growling )
Listen to that.
He sounds very angry...
really...
really aggressive.
What do you
think he wants?
Do you think he's
responding to some...
some predatory instinct?
( thumping )
Do you think he
sees us as prey?
There are crew members
in the corridors
and other sections
of the ship.
It would be easier
for him to capture
and consume one of them
than to attempt
to break through a door.
( growling )
Then what does he want?
Predators use vocalizations
to frighten other predators
and to mark territory...
and to commence
mating process.
A mating process...
Counselor Troi
was bitten by a Klingon,
but not in a place
that might be
life-threatening.
Nowhere near
a major artery or organ.
Data, look at this.
Look at this injury.
This wound was
never intended
to give her any
kind of serious harm.
Captain,
what are you suggesting?
Is it possible that
Worf could see Counselor
Troi as his mate?
If that is true,
he must be trying
to reach her now.
Well, we can't just leave.
We have to stay here
and protect her.
And we have to keep on
working on the retrovirus.
If we could distract him.
If we could lure him
away from her...
The mating instinct
is quite strong
in Klingon biology.
I am not certain
what would be an
effective lure.
Klingons have got a very
powerful sense of smell.
If we could duplicate
Deanna's pheromones
and then convince
him that she's no
longer in Sick Bay,
that she'd gone into some
other part of the ship...
I am extracting
a blood sample
from one of her
sebaceous glands
where the pheromones
are produced.
I believe I can
activate the pheromones
with a bioactivant
solution.
Can you amplify
the pheromones?
They need to be
much more powerful
than Deanna's
actual scent.
I believe this will
produce the desired effect.
I will use it to draw Worf
to another part of the ship.
No, no, no. You
must go on working
on the retrovirus.
I'll go.
Captain, that is extremely
unwise. Worf may be faster...
No time...
No time to argue.
( growling )
( growling, sniffing )
( spraying )
( growling )
Deck 17.
Deck 17!
( thumping and growling )
Computer, display
progress of genetic
re-sequencing.
( growling )
( yells )
COMPUTER:
Genetic re-sequencing
in progress.
DNA to 70% normal.
Computer,
increase nucleotide
substitution by 32%.
( growling )
( roaring )
Data to Captain Picard.
Go ahead, Data.
The retrovirus
is working, sir.
I can release it into
the ship's atmosphere
in a gaseous state.
However, it will take
some time to take effect.
Acknowledged!
Are you all right, sir?
Yes, I'm fine, Mr. Data.
Proceed.
( breathing heavily )
Well, Mr. Worf...
let's hope that
when you wake up,
you're a new man.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
Commander Data has
succeeded in returning
the crew to normal.
Dr. Crusher has
determined that the
synthetic T cell she used
to cure Mr. Barclay's
Urodelean flu
initiated the intron
virus, which swept
through the ship.
So, this is my fault.
No. In a way,
it's mine.
I didn't realize
it at the time,
but there's an anomaly
in your genetic chemistry
that caused the synthetic
T cell to mutate.
Instead of activating
one dormant gene,
it started activating
all of them, including
your introns.
And that's what...
( softer ):
And that's what caused
me to de-evolve?
You and every other
member of the crew.
The T cell became airborne
and started to spread
like a virus.
You know, Reg,
this is a completely
new disease
and it's traditional
to classify a new disease
with the name of the
first diagnosed patient.
Oh, you mean
you want to name
the disease after me?
That's right.
How about "Barclay's
Protomorphosis Syndrome"?
"Barclay's
Protomorphosis..."
Um, well...
it has a nice
ring to it.
Thank you, Doctor.
He transformed
into a spider
and now he has a disease
named after him.
I think I better
clear my calendar
for the next few weeks.