Captain's Log,
Stardate 47751.2.
The Enterprise has arrived
at Starbase 310
for a meeting
with Fleet Admiral Necheyev.
This visit has also given us
the opportunity
to pick up a member
of the family.
Here you are--
your very own quarters.
And they're as far away
from mine as possible
so you don't even have to
see me if you don't want to.
Mom, you know that's
not why I asked
for my own quarters
this time.
You don't have to explain.
There comes a time
in a young man's life
when he doesn't want to stay
with his poor, senile mother.
I understand.
I'll come visit you
in the old doctor's
home every Sunday.
( door chimes )
Come in.
So... is there
a runaway cadet in here?
If so, we may have
to call security.
Welcome back, Wes.
Thanks.
So, how's life
at the academy?
It's great.
It's great, but it's
good to have a break.
DATA:
I was, of course,
not serious about
calling security.
It was a joke.
I got it, Data.
So, you just going
to lounge around
while we all have work
to do around here?
I'm sure I can find some
time to help you, sir.
No, Wes.
Enjoy your vacation.
I'm sure
you've earned it.
Thanks.
Well, I think
we'd better let
you settle in.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Say, Wes, don't, uh...
don't sleep your whole
vacation away, all right?
Good-bye, Wes.
Oh... it's good
to have you home, son.
Thanks, Mom.
Really.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Admiral Necheyev has
just beamed aboard.
She's being escorted
right here.
Good.
Earl Grey tea,
watercress sandwiches
and Bularian canapés?
Are you up
for a promotion?
I am trying to establish
a new relationship
with the admiral.
There has been a certain
amount of tension
between us in the past.
"Tension" is hardly
the word I'd use.
Well, I am trying to get
things off on a better
note this time.
I want her to feel
at ease, I want her
to feel that she's welcome
onboard the Enterprise.
Is there any reason
she shouldn't feel
welcome here?
We don't have
to like her, Will,
but we have to
follow her orders,
and maintaining
this atmosphere
of confrontation
serves no purpose.
Admiral Necheyev,
welcome onboard
the Enterprise.
Thank you, Captain.
You may leave,
Commander Riker.
Thank you,
Admiral. Captain.
May I offer you some
refreshments, Admiral?
I'll come right
to the point, Captain.
There's a situation
that's developed
on the Cardassian
border that...
Are those
Bularian canapés?
Oh, as a matter
of fact, they are.
I... spoke with your aide,
Commander Wrightwell,
and he said that you were
particularly fond of them.
That was very thoughtful,
Captain.
Thank you.
Please.
You were saying
about the Cardassians...
Yes. The Federation
has just completed
a very long and drawn-out
series of negotiations
regarding the final
status of our border
with the Cardassians.
These will be the
official boundaries.
I see.
You'll notice a
demilitarized zone
has also been created
along the border.
Neither side
will be permitted to
place military outposts,
conduct fleet exercises,
or station warships
anywhere in the
demilitarized area.
This border places
several Federation colonies
in Cardassian territory
and some Cardassian
colonies in ours.
This agreement
is far from perfect.
Neither side got
everything they wanted
but every side got
something, and as
someone once said,
"Diplomacy is the art
of the possible."
Those colonies
finding themselves
on the wrong side
of the border
will have to be moved.
Well, the colonists
are not going to be
happy about that.
Some of them have
been there for decades.
It won't be easy,
but it's a reasonable
price to pay for peace.
Your mission will be
to evacuate the
colony on Dorvan V.
Dorvan V?
Isn't that where
the group of North
American Indians settled?
Yes, they've been there
for about 20 years.
They've established a
village in a small valley
on the southern continent.
Is something wrong?
Admiral, centuries ago,
these North American Indians
were forcibly displaced
from their ancestral lands.
These settlers on Dorvan V
originally left Earth
more than 200 years ago
in order to preserve
their cultural identity.
I am aware of that,
Captain.
You see, Admiral,
there are some
very disturbing
historical parallels here.
Once more, they are being
asked to leave their
homes because of a...
a political decision
that has been taken
by a distant government.
An Indian representative
was included
in the deliberations of
the Federation council.
His objections were
noted, discussed, but
ultimately rejected.
Captain,
the Indians on Dorvan
are a nomadic group
that have settled there
only 20 years ago
and, at that time,
they were warned
that the planet
was hotly disputed
by the Cardassians.
The bottom line is,
they never should
have gone there
in the first place.
Granted, but to go to
them now, after 20 years,
and ask them to leave
what is now their home...
I made that same argument
with the Federation council
but it took three years
to negotiate this treaty.
Some concessions had
to be made, and this
was one of them.
What if these Indians
refuse to be evacuated?
Then your orders will be
to remove them by whatever
means are necessary.
I understand your moral
objections, Captain.
If you wish,
I can find someone else
to command the Enterprise
for this mission.
That will not
be necessary, Admiral.
I don't envy you this task,
but I do believe it is
for the greater good.
I understand.
And, Captain...
thank you for...
making me feel welcome.
You will always be welcome
aboard this ship, Admiral.
Thanks, Ensign.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, Wes, there you are.
Come here for a second.
I've got something
I want to show you.
Come on, come on.
You got to take
a look at this.
Now, remember how we
always used to talk
about improving
quantum efficiency
by creating a new
plasma-dyne relay?
Well... take a look...
at this.
WES:
You've only got
one microfusion
interrelay in there?
Your converter interface
will never hold up.
Hey, I ran
these diagnostics myself.
This little baby
will withstand
over 500 cochranes
of warp field stress.
I don't think so.
You better put a second
phase inverter in there.
Look at your
subprocessor matrix.
It needs an overhaul.
Well, that may be
your opinion, Cadet,
but I stand by my work.
Read the latest paper
from Dr. Vassbinder.
He has brilliant
new theories
on warp-propulsion
interrelays.
He'd say all this stuff
is obsolete.
( sighing )
I don't know what's
gotten into you, Wes.
Look, do you want
my help or not?
With this kind of an
attitude, absolutely not.
You're dismissed.
( disgusted sigh )
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
The Enterprise has
arrived at Dorvan V
and I have spoken to the leader
of the tribal council.
He has agreed to meet
with us this afternoon
to discuss the situation.
Anthwara, there's
very little I can do.
The decision about
this planet was made
at the very highest
level of Starfleet.
Do you know how long we
have searched for a home?
Almost 200 years.
Then we found this world.
Can you blame us for not
wanting to give it up?
I understand, and I respect
your people's long journey,
but I believe
that I can help you
to find a new home.
TROI:
As you can see, there
are three other planets
in this sector that have
environmental conditions
similar to those
here on Dorvan V.
They're all
uninhabited and could
be colonized immediately.
And if none of these worlds
meets with your approval,
then we will find you
other choices.
You do not understand,
Captain.
The choice of this planet
was not only because of
environmental conditions.
There were other more...
intangible concerns
as well.
When I came here
20 years ago...
I was welcomed
by the mountains,
the rivers, the sky.
Anthwara, he's
laughing at you.
He thinks you're talking
about old superstition
and nonsense.
This is not true.
I have the deepest
respect for your beliefs
and the meaning
that they hold
for your people.
Then you can respect
the fact
that this planet holds
a deep spiritual
significance for us.
It has taken us two centuries
to find this place.
We do not want to spend
another 200 years
searching for what
we already have.
Captain, I suggest
we adjourn--
allow us all time
to think about
what's been said.
Agreed.
We will reconvene
tomorrow.
And in the meantime,
I would like
to invite you all
to join us this evening
on the Enterprise.
Thank you.
We look forward to it.
Ever since
you've come onboard,
you've been moody,
sullen, and rude.
What's going on?
Nothing. I just want
to be left alone.
That incident
in engineering
was inexcusable.
That is my business.
I don't need you telling
me how to behave.
I shouldn't have to.
You're a fourth-year
Starfleet cadet.
You should have
a certain level
of maturity.
Maybe I am sick
of following rules
and regulations.
Maybe I'm sick of living
up to everyone else's
expectations.
Did you ever
think of that?
( door opens, closes )
I have been fascinated,
looking into the
history and traditions
of your people,
and I was very interested
to learn that your
Grandfather Katowa
was the man who first led
the group of Indians
from Earth initially,
more than 200 years ago.
Hmm. There was a great
deal of opposition.
Even my own father
was against it.
But when Katowa
made his decision,
it was final.
My father never said
another word.
It's never easy to
leave one's home...
the safe and the familiar.
But there are times when...
the greater good
demands that certain...
sacrifices are made.
I'm sure
that was something
that your grandfather
understood.
So does his grandson.
There are also times...
when a people
sacrificed too much...
...when a people must
hold on to what we have,
even against
overwhelming opposition.
What do you know about
your family, Captain?
Um, well, a great
deal, actually.
My father was
a strong believer
in passing on the
traditions and history
of a family.
I would like to know
more about your family.
We have strong ties
to our ancestors.
We believe their actions
guide us... even now.
Knowing more
about your family
might help me
to better understand you.
Besides, it
is always good
to understand
one's adversary
in any negotiation.
I hope that by the
end of this matter,
you will
no longer look on me
as an adversary.
My family.
Well, um...
our roots in Western
Europe go back to the
time of Charlemagne.
There is a record
of a nobleman...
Sorry I'm late.
We'll talk
about it later.
MAN:
Wesley Crusher?
Yes?
I am Lakanta.
It's nice to meet you.
Can I get you
a drink or something?
I have known...
that you were coming to us
for the past two years.
Two years ago...
I went into the habak
and began a vision quest,
and while I was there,
I saw many things,
talked to many animals,
many spirits...
and I saw you.
I don't think
I understand.
I know why you came
to us, Wesley--
to find the answers
that you seek.
I just don't know
what to do, Jean-Luc.
It's as if somebody
took my son away
and left this stranger
in his place.
But in a sense, that's
exactly what happened.
When Wesley left
the Enterprise
three years ago,
he was a boy,
and now he has
returned a young man.
And that can't be
easy for a mother
or a son.
But it's gone beyond
just the two of us.
Yes, I heard about the
incident with Geordi.
Have you heard what
happened in the academy?
I called
Admiral Brand today.
She said his grades
are dropping,
that he's becoming
remote and defensive.
If he's not careful,
he's going to wash
out next term.
Maybe... maybe you should
talk to him, Jean-Luc.
Maybe it's the kind
of thing that a boy--
a man-- needs to discuss
with another man.
I don't think he wants
either of us to talk
to him right now.
But he needs our help.
But, Beverly, he's
got to want that help.
If he doesn't, then
any efforts on our part
could only push him
further away.
He's-- he's got
to... work this out
for himself.
How long have you
been watching me?
Since you beamed down.
Well, I'm here.
What should I do?
I don't know.
I thought you said
you were going to help me
find some answers.
Answers
to your questions.
Tell me about this habak.
You said you had some
kind of vision there?
The habak is holy to us.
We hold our rituals
and our ceremonies there.
It's sacred to us.
What's sacred to you,
Wesley?
I don't know.
I mean, I think
a lot of things
are important.
I have a lot of
respect for things,
but I don't really
consider anything sacred.
Look around us.
What do you think
is sacred to us here?
Maybe the necklace
you're wearing?
The designs on the walls?
Everything
is sacred to us.
The buildings,
the food, the sky,
the dirt beneath
your feet and you.
Whether you believe
in your spirit or not,
we believe in it.
You are a sacred
person here, Wesley.
I think that's the
first time anyone's used
that particular word
to describe me.
So, if you are sacred,
then you must treat
yourself with respect.
To do otherwise
is to desecrate
something that is holy.
Is that what you think
I've been doing?
Only you can
decide that.
I guess I haven't
had a lot of respect
for myself lately.
Then perhaps it's time
for your own vision
quest to begin.
Anthwara, I deeply regret
that we have not been able
to reach an agreement.
But-- and I must be
blunt-- I cannot take
no for an answer.
This planet will be
handed over to the
Cardassian government
in accordance with the terms
of the border agreement.
I'm very sorry, but
you will have to leave.
And if we do not?
Then I will be forced...
to remove you
by whatever means
are necessary.
We know you will
not take us from
this land, Captain.
I may regret it,
but I am not able...
When you first came to us,
we did not know
why you were sent
by the Federation,
but we knew there
must be a good reason.
To us, nothing that
happens is truly random.
So, we searched
for the true reason
you were sent,
and we did not find it
until last night.
Are you familiar
with the Pueblo
Revolt of 1680?
I am.
Several Indian tribes
rose up to overthrow
their Spanish overlords
and drove them
out of what is now
called New Mexico.
Ten years later,
the Spanish returned
to reconquer the area.
They were brutal.
I would use the word...
"savage."
They killed hundreds
of our people.
Thousands more
were maimed.
The name of one
of the soldiers
was Javier Maribona...
Picard...
your ancestor.
I'm not aware of this
incident or of the
man you named...
...and this happened
more than 700 years ago.
I do not see what
bearing it can have...
That is why you
have come to us--
to erase a stain of blood
worn by your family
for 23 generations.
( door opens )
( dog barking )
Mr. Worf,
what is going on?
We have unwelcome
visitors, sir.
I'm Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the Enterprise.
I am Gul Evek.
What are all these
people still doing here?
The evacuation should be
well underway by now.
May I have a word
with you... alone?
( sighing )
As you wish.
Wait here.
It was my understanding
that there would be
no Cardassian presence here
for another six weeks.
Your arrival here may
have upset some very
delicate negotiations.
Negotiations?
The status of this planet
has been settled.
What are you negotiating?
I will be very happy
to explain that to you,
but for now, I must
ask you and your men
to leave immediately.
Captain,
we have been sent here
to perform
a preliminary survey
of all the buildings
and equipment being
left behind.
I have no intention
of leaving
until our mission
is complete.
Very well.
Complete your mission,
but remember,
this is Federation
territory, Gul Evek,
and until that changes,
these people are under
my jurisdiction and
I will protect them.
Is that a threat?
It's a fact.
Bear that in mind while
you conduct your "survey."
This is the habak,
the focal point
of our lives.
Strangers are
not welcome here.
When I asked to come
here, you said that
it would be...
You're not a stranger.
I told you.
I've seen you here before.
What are those figures?
They are Mansara--
dolls that represent
the different spirits
that have come to
this place.
That one looks
like a Klingon.
Yes. Our culture
is rooted in the past,
but it's not
limited to the past.
The spirits of
the Klingon, the Vulcan,
and the Ferengi
come to us just as
the bear and the
coyote, the parrot.
There's no difference.
What should I do?
Start the fire.
And then sit and wait.
What am I waiting for?
This is your journey,
Wesley.
I can open the door,
but only you can go
through it.
Admiral, the Indian
council is adamant.
They refuse to
leave Dorvan V.
Is there any indication
the tribal council
will change their position
in the near future?
No, sir.
Then I see
no other choice.
Admiral, I have
every reason to believe
that they will resist
any attempt to remove them.
I strongly urge
you to request
an emergency session
of the Federation council.
The issue of Dorvan V
must be reopened.
Captain, I made that
request two days ago.
The answer was no.
I'm sorry,
but you have your orders.
Starfleet out.
So much for your reprieve
from Starfleet.
( sighs )
Anthwara believes...
that I am responsible
for the crimes
of one of my ancestors
against his people.
Do you believe that?
No, of course not.
I respect his belief,
but I do not see
how it can have any
bearing on this mission.
But even so,
I can't help wondering...
if a dark chapter
in my family's history
is about to be repeated.
If those people
take up arms against us,
then I cannot foresee
the consequences.
Mr. Worf, will you
come in here a moment?
Aye, sir.
Mr. Worf, will you
begin preparations
to remove the inhabitants
from Dorvan V?
Aye, sir.
Wesley.
Dad?
You've reached
the end, Wesley.
The end of what?
This journey--
one you started
a long time ago...
when I left you
and your mother.
You mean when you died.
You set out on a journey
that wasn't your own.
Now it's time to find
a path that is truly yours.
Don't follow me
any further.
I don't understand.
Yes, you do.
It's just hard
for you to accept.
Good-bye, Wesley,
and good luck.
Dad, wait!
( gasps )
Mr. Crusher.
Are you all right?
Yeah, Worf, I'm fine.
Lay out a
confinement beam trace
along the southeastern
side of the village,
but be discreet.
We do not wish to
alarm these people.
Yes, sir.
Worf?
What are you doing?
We are laying out
transporter coordinates
for a security perimeter.
It may be necessary
to remove these people
by force.
Worf...
we can't do this.
These people deserve
better than to be
removed from their homes.
I understand, but
now is not the time.
Do you know what
they're trying to do?
They're preparing to
beam you away and take
you to their ship.
You're not going to let
them do that, are you?
No.
No, we won't.
Leave now.
Yeah!
Inexcusable.
You defied the orders
of the ranking officer
on the scene.
You put the lives
of the entire away
team in jeopardy,
and you made
an already tense
situation worse.
Your actions reflect
very badly on this ship
and on that uniform.
Now, I want an
explanation, Mr. Crusher,
and I want it now.
What you're doing
down there is wrong.
These people are not
some random group
of colonists.
They're a unique culture
with a history
that predates the
Federation and Starfleet.
That does not alter
the fact that my
orders are to...
I know Admiral Necheyev
gave you an order,
and she was given
an order from the
Federation council,
but it's still wrong.
That decision is not
yours to make, Cadet.
I don't know what has
got into you lately,
and frankly, right now,
I don't care.
But I will tell you
this-- while you
wear that uniform,
you will obey every
order you are given
and you will conform
to Starfleet regulations
and rules of conduct.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir, it is,
but I won't be wearing
this uniform any longer.
I'm resigning
from the academy.
( badge drops )
( door opens, closes )
Riker to Captain.
Go ahead, Number One.
Gul Evek
wants to meet with you
to discuss the situation
on the surface.
Let him come aboard.
I'll see him in here.
Aye, sir.
Why are you doing this?
I told you.
Starfleet isn't for me.
Look, I may not
be able to stop you
from throwing away
your entire life,
but you are going to
stand here and explain
it to me first.
You owe me that much.
I saw Dad today.
He told me not
to follow him.
You what?
I was participating
in an Indian ritual
and I had a vision.
Dad came to me and told
me not to follow him.
He said I had to
find my own path.
Is that what
this is all about?
A vision told you
to leave the academy,
and now you're
packing your bags?
No. No, it's
more than that.
I've known
I needed to do this
for a long time.
I just haven't been able
to admit it to myself.
But you always said
that being at the academy
was the best thing that
ever happened to you.
I know.
For a while, it was.
But as time went on
and graduation got closer,
I... I started feeling
really depressed.
I thought maybe
it was the workload
or the stress
of being away from home,
but it didn't go away.
It just got worse.
( sighing )
Why didn't you
ever say anything?
I didn't want to
disappoint you or Captain
Picard or my friends.
You guys were
all so proud of me.
I'd be proud of you
no matter what you
were doing, Wesley.
I love you.
I know, Mom.
I guess the truth is
that I was afraid of
disappointing myself.
I never questioned
the fact that I would
be in Starfleet,
but when Dad said
not to follow him,
it just made
so much sense.
Everything is
so clear now.
Maybe it is partly
my fault.
We didn't realize
the kind of pressure
we were putting on you
to be exactly what we
expected you to be.
Oh, I don't blame
you at all.
This is my decision.
It always has been.
You know that... alien...
from Tau Ceti--
the one who could control
warp fields with his mind?
The traveler.
He told Captain Picard
a long time ago
that you were very
special, like Mozart...
and that you were
destined for something
quite different
from the rest of us.
Maybe this is
the first step.
I love you.
I love you, too, Mom.
You shouldn't
be here, Wesley.
Why?
Get down there!
Bring them over here.
Why have you taken
these men prisoner?
This is not their world.
They have no right
to be here.
The terms of the treaty
gives them the right
to survey this planet.
We don't recognize
that treaty.
( indistinct shouting )
Worf to Picard.
An armed group of
Indians has taken two
Cardassian prisoners.
The situation
is extremely volatile.
Request instructions.
Stand by, Mr. Worf.
Have your ship
lock on to your people
and beam them out of there
before something happens.
My people? What about
these Indians of yours?
They've taken hostages!
This is our planet,
Captain.
We will not
be chased away
by some unruly crowd.
Gul Evek to the Vetar.
This is Glinn Telak
aboard the Vetar.
Go ahead.
Two of our men on
the surface have
been taken prisoner.
Prepare to send an
armed squad of troopers
to rescue them and
to occupy the village.
Gul Evek, those people
are Federation citizens
and I am sworn
to protect them.
If your troops
attack that village,
my security forces
will respond.
I hope you realize
the consequences
of Federation officers
firing on Cardassian troops.
Oh, yes, I do.
That is why
we must stop this now
before it's too late.
I cannot allow you
to hold these men
as prisoners.
You have no
authority here.
( grunting )
No!
What happened?
Did you do this?
( chuckles )
I didn't do
anything; you did.
I did?
You pulled yourself
out of their time.
You took the
first step, Wesley.
My first step to where?
To another plane
of existence...
another way of thinking.
I don't understand.
You found a new
beginning for yourself--
the first step
on a journey
that few humans
will ever take.
Who are you?
The traveler.
I've waited a long time
for this moment, Wesley.
So, all those things
I saw in the habak--
my father and the things
he said to me--
that was your doing?
I merely opened
the door for you.
What you experienced
came from your own mind--
your own...
spirit, if you wish.
I hoped that you
would open your mind
to new possibilities,
and you did.
You pulled yourself out
of time, don't you see?
You've evolved
to a new level.
You're ready to
explore places
where thought
and energy combine
in ways you can't
even imagine.
And I will
be your guide...
if you like.
What about them?
I can't just leave
them like this.
They must find their
own destinies, Wesley.
It's not our place
to... interfere.
But--
Have faith
in their abilities
to solve their
problems on their own.
( yelling )
The Cardassian ship
is powering its weapons
and its transporters.
This is the Vetar to Gul Evek.
Our troops are under attack.
They're requesting
immediate assistance.
What are your orders?
Evek, the last war
caused massive destruction
and cost millions of lives.
Don't send our two
peoples down that same
path again-- not like this.
Now the future lies
in your hands, right now.
Give us one last chance
for peace.
Gul Evek,
what are your orders?
Can we open fire?
Evek to the Vetar.
Lock on our troops
on the surface...
and beam them aboard.
But, sir,
they've been fired upon!
Those are my orders!
Carry them out.
Yes, sir.
Beam up the away
team immediately.
Aye, sir.
I lost two of three sons
in the war, Captain.
I don't want to lose
the last one.
Anthwara, I want to
be absolutely sure
that you understand
the implications
of this agreement.
By giving up your status
as Federation citizens,
any future request
you or your people
make to Starfleet
will go unanswered.
You will be
on your own...
and under Cardassian
jurisdiction.
I understand, Captain,
and we are prepared
to take that risk.
Will the Cardassian
government honor
your agreement here?
I believe
I can convince them
that this is
an equitable solution.
I cannot speak for
every Cardassian
you may encounter,
but if you leave us
alone, I suspect that
we will do the same.
Will this be acceptable
to the Starfleet command?
It will not be easy,
but with Admiral
Necheyev's support,
I think they will go
along with it in the end.
Then, if there's
nothing else, I will
return to my ship.
I have a rather lengthy
report to write.
Captain. Anthwara.
I was right, Captain.
You did not take us
from our land,
and you have wiped
clean a very old
stain of blood.
( door opens, closes )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47755.3.
The Enterprise is
preparing to leave Dorvan V,
but former Cadet Wesley Crusher
will be staying behind.
Where will you go?
The traveler said
that my studies would
begin with these people.
He said that they're
aware of many things.
I can learn
a lot from them.
That's just what I need--
more studying.
Somehow,
I think you'll manage.
Me, too.
Well, good luck,
Mr...
Good luck, Wesley.
Thank you...
for a lot of things.
Oh...
Now, you be sure
and dress warmly
on those other planes
of existence.
I will.
Bye, Mom.
Good-bye.
PICARD:
Energize.