As time passes,
a boy inevitably becomes a man,
but what is not inevitable
is that a man become a warrior.
A warrior must be forged,
like a sword,
tempered by...
by...
tempered by experience.
The path of the warrior
begins with--
( giggling )
Alexander?
No! Wait!
( child giggling )
Sorry.
I didn't mean to hit you.
What is the meaning of this?
I'm sorry.
We made fullerenes
in chemistry class today
and filled them
with water.
I asked you to meet me here
after school.
I have been waiting
for you.
I forgot.
You forgot because
you allowed yourself
to be distracted
by foolishness.
I'm sorry.
( sighs )
There is something
very important
I want to discuss
with you.
It concerns
your future.
Sit.
As time passes,
a boy inevitably
becomes a man,
but what is
not inevitable
is that a man
becomes a sword.
What?
No, I meant...
warrior.
The path of
a warrior begins
with the First
Rite of Ascension.
Is that when they hit you
with painstiks?
No. No, that is
the Second Rite.
Oh.
You are approaching
the Age of Ascension.
It is time for you to
prepare for the ceremony.
What do I have to do?
Well, your fighting
skills will be tested,
and your knowledge of
the teachings of Kahless.
It will be
challenging,
but I will help you
prepare.
These are the
kor'tova candles.
They represent
the fire that burns
within the heart
of a warrior.
When you light yours,
you will be declaring
your intention
to become a warrior.
Go ahead.
What if I don't
want to?
If you do not
participate in the rite
before the age of 13 years,
you will never be able
to become a true
Klingon warrior.
Well, I don't care
about that.
You may not care
about it now,
but someday you might.
Well, Mother always
said that--
that I didn't have to
do any of
this Klingon stuff
if I didn't want to.
It is your decision,
but--
Okay, then.
I'm not going to
do it.
Alexander.
You just said
it was up to me.
I don't want to be
a warrior.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
As a result, we won't
be able to rendezvous
with the Kearsarge
for another four days.
Will we be holding position
here until it arrives?
Yes, and as
it would seem
that we're in for
a relatively quiet time,
I shall use
this opportunity
to visit
the Hatarian system.
There are some
ancient ruins
that are just
being excavated.
The delay will also
make it possible
for stellar dynamics
to complete their study
of the Vodrey Nebula.
I'll let them know
that they can have
more access to the
lateral sensor grid.
We could use
this time
to recalibrate the weapons
targeting system.
Mr. Worf?
Yes, um...
I will begin
the procedure immediately.
Very good.
Dismissed.
Lieutenant?
Could I have a word
with you for a moment?
I noticed several times
during the briefing
that you appeared
to be a bit distracted.
I apologize.
In the future,
I will make sure
my personal
affairs do not
interfere with
my duties.
Is everything
all right?
I'm having problems
with Alexander.
He has made it clear
he does not wish
to participate in the
First Rite of Ascension.
Oh, I see.
I tried to tell him
that it is
an important part of
a young Klingon's life,
but... he does
not understand.
But he's had
so little opportunity
to spend time
with Klingons.
You know, the Festival
of Kot'baval is tomorrow.
If he could
take part in that,
I'm sure he would
more fully appreciate
what a rich cultural
heritage he comes from.
There is the Klingon
outpost on Maranga IV.
I'm sure they'll be
celebrating the festival.
Yes...
but the outpost is
on the other side
of the Vodrey Nebula.
It would take three days
by shuttle to get there.
Oh, the Enterprise
could be there
in a fraction of the time,
and still back
in time for
the rendezvous.
Captain, I could
not ask you--
Mr. Worf, stellar dynamics
would like
nothing better than
a trip around the nebula.
Thank you, sir.
KLINGON MALES:
♪ Huya! ♪
♪ Eu-uh ha', eu-uh ha'! ♪
♪ Ha'! ♪
♪ Nika tai kai te-blah ♪
♪ Ni'tokor o-ta-ke ta kor ♪
♪ Euh! Yah ki-tach cha'! ♪
( speaking Klingon )
♪ ...Ke'te ha' ♪
♪ Ke euh kai ka chu' ♪
♪ Yah ke'te cha' ♪
♪ Yah! ♪
( crowd exclaiming )
♪ Ke le qapla' tah! ♪
♪ Ragateth bat'leth! Eh! ♪
♪ Yake euh hiya keeu ♪
♪ Che yu ♪
♪ Euh! Ha'! Ha'! ♪
♪ Ha'! ♪
( grunts )
♪ Ragateth bat'leth... ♪
Who's that?
It is the tyrant Molor.
He was so strong,
no one could stand against him.
♪ Nok'tar be'got
hosh'ar te'not ♪
What's he saying?
He is asking
if anyone else
will have the courage
to stand up to Molor.
♪ Hosh'ar te'not ♪
♪ Kate qapla' plakmara ♪
♪ Ki'rok Molor ♪
♪ Ki'rok ♪
♪ Ni'kotor bak'to ♪
♪ Ba'jak tu'mo ♪
( grunting )
♪ O'tak tu'ro! ♪
( grunting fiercely )
( groaning )
( booing and hissing )
♪ Nok'tar be'got ♪
♪ Hosh'ar te'not? ♪
( grunts )
( indistinct voices )
( scattered applause )
♪ Ki'rok, Molor! Ki'rok! ♪
What is this?
( grunting )
( grunting and groaning )
Jik'ta!
You wounded me!
( cheers and applause )
You fought well.
What happens now?
There is only one man who
can stand against Molor.
♪ Nik'tol Kahless... ♪
It's Kahless!
Kahless would rather die
than live under
Molor's tyranny.
♪ Molor gik'tal! ♪
Ni'lot Kahless!
( distant music and laughter )
Father!
Where have you been?
We were watching
the fire dancers.
We?
K'nor and Bar'el.
They live here
on the outpost.
I need some money.
What for?
Well, a man over there
says he has
Molor's head in a box--
the real Molor.
That is impossible.
The real Molor died
centuries ago.
I know-- it's mummified.
He offered to show us
for 50 darseks.
He is trying
to take your money.
Please, Father,
he's waiting.
No, it is too late.
We should go home.
But I--
Alexander,
that is enough.
Come, it is time
to go.
I have to say good-bye
to my friends.
You can see your friends
again tomorrow.
We're coming back?
If you want to.
( speaking Klingon )
Ah!
Run, Alexander!
( grunting and groaning )
Ni'tokor bak'to!
K'pla, Worf.
You were too much
for them.
I have seen you before.
Who are you?
A friend.
You are K'mtar.
Your brother sent me
here to protect you.
He is gin'tak
to the House of Mogh.
Gin'tak?
An adviser so trusted,
he has become
part of the family.
Do you have any idea who
was behind the attack?
It is a Klingon matter.
It is not
your concern.
One of my officers
was almost killed.
That makes it
my concern.
Recently, rumors began
to circulate on the homeworld
that an assassination attempt
was going to be made
on the family of Mogh.
Kurn sent me here to make sure
nothing happened to Worf.
Why didn't you warn him
before the attack was made?
I tried to contact him
over subspace.
I was told
he was not aboard.
I decided to beam directly
to the surface.
And why didn't you
let us know about it?
Forgive me for being blunt,
Commander,
but when it comes
to protecting the House
to which I have pledged
my life...
I trust no one.
I have full confidence
in the officers
with whom I serve.
One of the attackers
dropped this dagger.
The design represents
the house of Duras.
We have other evidence
that indicate
the Duras sisters,
Lursa and B'etor
were behind
the attack.
What do you think
they were after?
Kurn's seat on the council,
of course.
We cannot allow their attack
on our house to go unanswered.
First, we must find them.
At one point,
they were on Deep Space 9
trying to sell
bilitrium explosives.
That was months ago.
No one knows
where they went from there.
Maybe we can
find them.
We've arranged for
quarters on the ship
if you'd like
to stay.
I would.
Worf and I have much
to discuss.
I will send Kurn a message
telling him what happened,
but he will not
receive it for days.
He's gone to
the Hitora colony--
Why did you treat
Commander Riker
so disrespectfully?
You were rude!
I may have been rude
by human standards.
I meant no disrespect.
What is the
matter, Worf?
Have you been living
so long among humans
that you have forgotten
how Klingons behave?
I have not forgotten.
I am merely stating
that their ways are
different than ours.
I trust you have
made your son
aware of that fact,
as well.
Yes, of course
I have.
Good.
Because someday,
Alexander
may be called upon
to lead the House of Mogh.
Kurn has no male heir.
He wants to make sure
that Alexander
is preparing himself.
Does my brother doubt
my ability to raise
my son as a Klingon?
No.
But you are alone
among humans.
It cannot be easy
to keep our ways.
No.
It has not been easy.
How are his
fighting skills?
Can he handle
a bat'leth?
He is learning.
He could be better.
He must.
He is nearing
the Age of Ascension.
Actually, Alexander
has not yet committed himself
to undergoing the rite.
What?
I have tried
to explain to him
how important
it is, but...
he will not
listen to me.
Perhaps together,
you and I,
we can find
a way to spark
the boy's interest
in his heritage.
I would be grateful for
any help you could offer.
Tomorrow, then.
Tomorrow.
May I say good night
to the boy?
Yes, of course.
Is this your mother?
Yeah.
She died when
I was little.
You miss her a great
deal, don't you?
It must be
hard for you
being the only Klingon
your age aboard this ship.
Sometimes.
Have you ever been
to the homeworld?
No.
I think you would
like it there.
At your uncle's house,
there is a lake
you can swim in
that is so clear
you can see all
the way to the bottom.
ALEXANDER:
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You have cousins there.
They want to meet you.
I don't know.
I understand.
You're afraid.
You don't know whether
the homeworld is safe.
Yeah.
And what happened today
on the planet
is frightening.
You're still troubled.
I thought they were going
to kill my father.
You must have wanted
to help us
fight them off.
I didn't know
what to do.
Someday,
if you work hard,
you will become
a warrior--
a Klingon warrior.
And you will always
feel safe
because you will know
how to defend yourself.
And I'll tell you
something else.
If anyone
ever tries
to hurt your
father again,
you will be able to fight
at his side
and make sure
nothing happens to him.
What do you think of that?
Good night, Alexander.
Dream well.
Good night, K'mtar.
Any luck?
Starfleet records
contain no mention
of the Duras sisters
after their departure
from Deep Space 9.
Did I not
tell you as much?
Have you been able
to contact Deep Space 9?
I am being patched through
right now, sir.
On screen.
Quark, I see
you remember me.
How could I forget
the only man ever to win
triple-down dabo
at one of my tables?
And how can I forget
that you didn't have
enough latinum
to cover my winnings?
I thought I explained
that my brother misplaced
the key to the safe.
Besides, those vouchers
I gave you
were every bit
as good as latinum.
You can spend latinum
almost anywhere.
Those vouchers are
only good at your bar.
Is, um... that what
this is about?
You're on your way
and you're calling
to reserve
a holosuite program?
Actually, I was hoping you could
help me with something else.
What would that be?
I'm looking for
some Klingon friends of mine--
the Duras sisters,
Lursa and B'etor.
Yes!
Big talk, small tips.
Do you know
where I can find them?
Well, I did hear
a rumor, actually.
What kind of rumor?
Oh, I don't know.
I'm sure it was told me
in confidence.
And how much would
your confidence cost?
How many vouchers
do you have again?
I have enough
for 12 bars of latinum.
I'd be glad
to return them.
I believe the rumor was
that the sisters
were trying to buy
some secondhand
mining equipment.
What for?
They learned of
a magnesite deposit on
the Kalla system.
It belongs to the Pakleds,
but those fools don't
even know it's there.
Your, uh, friends
are trying to get at it.
All right.
I'll send those vouchers
to you.
Oh, don't bother.
I voided them while
we've been talking.
So long, Quark.
How long would it take us
to get to the Kalla system?
Approximately
16 hours, sir.
Could not
he have been lying?
Why would he?
I'd just be knocking
on his door again in a few days,
and I wouldn't be in
as good a mood.
Uh-huh.
Congratulations,
Commander.
I did not think
it would be possible
to find the sisters.
Take us out of orbit.
ENSIGN:
Aye, sir.
I took the liberty
of creating a
holodeck program.
What kind of program?
I'll show you.
Computer, run program
K'mtar alpha one.
Program initiated.
Enter when ready.
Why did you want
to recreate this?
You said you wished
you had been able
to help
your father fight,
but you did not
know how.
You have probably
fought that battle
over and over again
in your mind.
Yes.
Let's see
what happens now.
Computer, give me
two Klingon warriors!
How can I fight
someone that big?
Size is not
the most important thing.
Skill, cunning,
powers of observation
are the most
important weapons.
Ni'tokor bak'to!
( grunting and groaning )
Freeze program.
Look what this
ko'tal is doing, hmm.
You see his leg?
That will give you
a clue
as to what
his next move will be.
All his weight is
on his right foot.
Yes, he is going to have to
shift it to regain his balance.
Stand ready!
Computer, resume program.
( grunting and groaning )
Po'tajg! Po'tajg!
Finish him.
( growling )
K'MTAR:
Freeze program!
You should have killed him
when you had the chance.
Why did you not?
I-- I don't know.
Look at him!
He did not care that
you showed him mercy!
He was going to
kill you!
K'mtar, that is enough.
If this was real,
he'd be dead by now.
Alexander!
We are approaching
Kalla III.
Set a standard orbit.
Any evidence of
a mining expedition?
A shaft has been cut
through the outer crust.
There is evidence
of machinery,
but it does not appear
to be in use.
Life signs?
It is difficult to say.
The magnesite is interfering
with bio-readings.
Assemble an away team.
Who are you?
Gorta.
I'm Gorta.
What are you doing
on this planet?
I crashed here.
DATA:
Then you are denying
involvement
in illegal mining
activities?
GORTA:
Mining?
So, that's what all
this equipment is here for.
We are looking
for two Klingon women.
Sisters.
Lursa? B'etor?
Do you know
where they are?
Actually, we were
hoping that you did.
M-Maybe I do.
Would you be willing to share
your information with us?
My personal code of conduct
prohibits sharing.
But I'd consider
a trade.
Does your personal code
of conduct tell you
that when you're stranded
on a planet with no way off
you shouldn't try
to cut deals?
You have a point.
We could certainly provide
passage off this planet
in exchange
for information.
Could you perhaps
fail to tell the Pakleds
that we were mining
their ore?
LA FORGE:
Don't push your luck.
But if you get us
the Duras sisters,
I'll see what
I can do.
Ahh.
The Duras sisters.
Oh, they are magnificent,
aren't they?
Where are they now?
Selling the ore,
I imagine.
They took everything--
the ore, the ship.
And where have they gone?
We were going to sell the ore
to a Yridian trader.
We were supposed to meet him
in the Ufandi system.
Gather your belongings.
It is time to leave.
( clanking )
Like I said,
they took everything.
Worf...
I am sorry
about what happened.
I should not have
gotten so angry.
It's just that
I am...
worried about
Alexander.
As am I.
Kurn told me
that his mother
actively
discouraged him
exploring his Klingon
heritage.
When he first came
to live with me,
he knew nothing
of our ways.
He often reminds me
of the things his
mother said to him.
And I try not to
disregard her wishes.
I want the boy
to honor his mother.
Mm.
Someday, I'm sure,
he will appreciate you
and be grateful for all
that you have done for him.
But still, compared
to other boys his age,
his fighting skills
are years behind.
Yes, I know.
He does not put in
the time it takes
to learn the skills.
Mm.
I thought that you
might consider
sending him to the
training academy at Ogat.
Your brother is
an influential man.
I'm sure he could
see to it
that Alexander
was admitted.
Ogat...
I am only thinking of what
is best for the boy.
There he would learn
our ways.
He would live
like a Klingon.
I would like him
to learn our ways.
No.
This is his home.
How...
How can you expect him
to lead our family
when all he knows is life
aboard a Federation
starship?
He is my son.
He belongs with me.
The boy is more human
than Klingon.
If he stays here,
he will never be a warrior.
He will never
be able to defend
our family against
its enemies!
Enough! Enough!
Enough! The decision
is mine!
Not necessarily.
I would be well
within my rights
to invoke ya'nora kor.
You would question my fitness
to raise my own son?
For the good of
our house,
yes, Worf.
I beg of you,
please stop thinking
of yourself.
It is Alexander
we should be considering.
Look into your heart...
and do what is best
for him.
Kahless was determined
to teach his brother a lesson
because he had told
a lie.
But Morath refused
to fight him
and instead ran away.
Kahless pursued him
across the valleys,
over the mountains,
and down to
the edge of the sea.
And there, at the shore,
they fought for 12--
12 days, 12 nights.
I know.
I've heard
this story before.
Hmm.
Alexander, it is important
to tell these stories
even though
we already know them.
Well, why was
Kahless so mad
about the lie
his brother told?
It made him look
like a coward.
If Kahless would have just
explained what happened,
maybe they wouldn't
have had to fight about it.
You're missing
the point.
Why was it so wrong
for Morath to run away?
Maybe he didn't want
to fight his brother
because he didn't want
to have to kill him.
He ran because
he was a coward.
But how do you
know that's why--
No, no, no, no.
No more questions.
These are our stories.
It is important for
a warrior to learn
how to interpret
them properly.
I'm trying to.
No, your head is filled
with foolish human notions
about how things are.
You are Klingon!
It is time you began
to act like one.
I am part human, too.
Listen to me,
Alexander.
When a human looks at you,
he does not see himself.
He sees a Klingon.
It doesn't matter
what I look like.
It does.
You are different than
everyone else aboard this ship.
That's not true!
It is.
The only way that
you will ever feel
as if you truly belong
is to leave here
and go and live
with your own kind.
I know a Klingon school
you could go to.
Oh, you would
be welcome there.
They would teach you
to be a warrior--
prepare you for
the Rite of Ascension.
I don't know if
I want to do that.
After you were there
for a while,
you would find that
you wouldn't want
to do anything else.
I don't want to leave
the Enterprise.
Alexander, you must!
Everything depends
upon it!
I thought
you were different.
you understood me,
but you don't!
You're just
like my father.
All you care about
is me becoming
a warrior.
Just leave me alone!
RIKER:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 47779.4.
We've entered
the Ufandi system
where we believe
the Duras sisters
might have come to sell the ore
they mined on Kalla III.
I am detecting a vessel
holding position near
the third planet.
It is a Yridian
freighter.
Put it on screen.
RIKER:
Scan for magnesite
in its hold.
The resonance
signature indicates
that there is
magnesite ore present.
Then we're too late.
The sisters have
already been here.
Somehow, I doubt the
Yridians are going to be
forthcoming about where
they might have gone.
DATA:
Sir...
readings indicate that
there are only 500
kilograms of ore in
the Yridian hold.
There should be
over 10,000 kilograms.
That's odd.
Hail them.
I'm Commander
William Riker from
the Federation starship
Enterprise.
I am Yog.
Why are we speaking?
Our sensors indicate
that you are carrying
magnesite ore.
Magnesite. Yes.
Where did you get it?
From a... Corvallan.
For a good price.
Where is this
Corvallan now?
I'm under orders
to acquire some magnesite.
Well, he is gone.
Where?
Who is to know?
Would you be interested
in selling me
the ore
that you're carrying?
No.
I have a buyer.
You haven't heard
my offer.
Half a gram
of Anjoran biomimetic gel.
Hmm.
Done.
Once we verify the purity
of your ore,
we'll beam over the gel.
You're up to something.
Have the transporter
room beam the ore
to these coordinates.
DATA:
Sir?
That would
place the ore
directly off the ship's
starboard bow.
I know.
Transport complete.
RIKER:
Lock the phasers
on the ore and fire.
Firing.
A Klingon Bird-of-Prey.
Put a tractor beam
on it.
How did you know?
The Yridians
had only part
of the shipment
in their hold.
I realized
that we had arrived
before they had completed
the transfer.
The Klingon ship
is hailing us.
On screen.
Release our vessel
at once!
I don't think so.
B'ETOR:
We've done nothing wrong.
We were engaging in a simple
business transaction.
We know you're dealing
in stolen ore...
but I want to talk
about the assassination attempt
on Lieutenant Worf.
What assassination
attempt?
This is the first
I've heard of it.
Too bad it
didn't succeed!
(sisters laughing)
We have evidence
that you're behind it.
That is outrageous!
What is this evidence?
Beam over.
We'll show you.
We'll be there...
shortly.
This was dropped by one
of the assassins.
It bears the crest
of your house.
Ge'ko... kaf'la.
Someone must have given
it to the assassins
to implicate us.
( scoffs )
Why would someone
do that?
B'ETOR:
In order
to tarnish
our good name.
You cannot tarnish
a rusted blade.
( hissing )
Ji'ko to'val!
Gir'nak tovo'sor!
RIKER:
Mr. Worf!
You said there was
other evidence
that they were involved?
Yes.
On the homeworld.
We'll set a course.
I want this thing cleared up.
I will send a message
to Kurn.
He may wish to return
to the homeworld, as well.
B'ETOR:
Bet'ala nog'tor.
Impossible!
What is it?
These markings represent
the members of our house.
This symbol represents our
father, myself, my sister...
and this...
represents... her son.
I was not aware
you had a son.
I do not.
But I am with child.
She found out
only a few days ago,
and told no one
but me.
How can this marking
be here?
Where did this come from?
I will speak with K'mtar.
( grunts )
Father...
stop!
I am your son.
I am Alexander.
What are you saying?
I am your son,
Alexander.
I have come to this time
from 40 years in the future.
P'tak.
Tell me
the truth or I will
kill you.
Look at me.
When we first met,
you said I looked familiar.
I could have seen you
on the homeworld.
No!
Look closely.
I am your son.
If you are Alexander,
you will remember
your mother's last words
before she died.
I was three years old.
She was dying
when we found her.
She barely managed
to whisper my name,
and then she took my hand
and placed it in yours.
Then she died,
and then you
howled in rage...
and said,
"Look upon her.
"Look upon death
and always remember."
and I always have.
( coughing )
How have
you done this--
come to this time?
I met a man in
the Cambra system.
He gave me a chance
to change the past.
He had the ability
to send me here
to this time.
And you came here in order
to end your own life?
I was hoping that
I would not have to...
that I could
change things,
change myself.
But I could not.
And now, everything
is going to turn out
like it did before.
I cannot
let that happen.
But why? What is
going to happen
that is so terrible?
You will be killed,
because I was
too naive,
too weak to be able
to protect you.
I do not believe that.
I was there.
I saw you murdered!
I was to blame!
You must not
blame yourself.
You don't understand.
I did not become
a warrior.
I was a...
a diplomat, a peacemaker.
When it came my time
to lead our family,
I thought that
I could single-handedly
end the fighting between
the great houses.
I publicly announced
that the House of Mogh
would be the first
to end the feuding,
that there would
be no more retribution,
no more revenge.
You tried to warn me.
You tried to tell me
that I should not
show weakness,
but I thought you were
a foolish old man.
I told you you were a relic
from an earlier time,
and that a new era
of peace was at hand.
But you were right.
My enemies saw my weakness
and moved against me.
And unless
I stop it right now,
that boy will see his father
killed on the floor
of the great
council chamber.
Ah, that is why you wanted
to take Alexander away--
to turn him
into a warrior.
I staged
the assassination attempt
to try and frighten him,
to make him realize
that he must follow
the ways of the warrior.
If I had listened
to you--
if I had become
the warrior
that you had
wanted me to be--
you would not have died
in my arms.
No.
Who knows what
the future will be
now that you have
disrupted time?
I may die tomorrow,
or I may outlive you.
But when I die,
I would like
an honorable death.
And the only way
that is possible
is for you to accept
yourself as you are
and stay true
to what you believe.
The cause of peace
is a just cause.
The struggle
must continue.
It is a futile struggle.
I cannot change things.
You have already
changed things
more than you realize.
The boy I was
has not changed.
But I have.
You have given me a glimpse
into my son's future,
and I know now that
he has his own destiny.
And I believe it
will be a great one.
I love you, Father.
And I you, Alexander.
I have been waiting.
Where is K'mtar?
He had to leave.
He was called away.
He never said
good-bye.
He asked me to say
good-bye for him.
He also wanted me
to tell you,
no matter what happens,
no matter what you decide
to do with your life,
he will always care
for you a great deal.
When will
I see him again?
It may be a long time.
Well, we should
start practice.
Alexander...
there will be plenty
of time for training.