Report.
There's an object of some kind
closing in on our position.
On screen.
DATA:
It appears
to be an unmanned probe.
Approximately one-half
meter in diameter.
There are
no identifiable armaments.
Captain,
we are being...
You are being hailed,
by name.
Open a channel.
This is Captain
Jean-Luc Picard of...
Captain, I am reading
a power surge.
Shields up.
DATA:
The beam appears to contain
holographic imaging
information.
It's trying
to project something.
Isolate
the bandwidth.
Let the signal
through the shields.
Bok.
I trust you remember
me, Picard,
because I haven't
forgotten you
or how you murdered
my son.
For 15 years now,
I've thought
about how to avenge his death,
but nothing I could do to you
could equal what you did
to me-- until now.
You thought you could
hide him from me, didn't you?
But I found out
about him.
Jason Vigo is
as good as dead.
I'm going to kill
your son, Picard,
just like you
killed mine.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Mr. Worf, put a tractor beam
on that probe.
Determine if it's safe
to beam it on board.
I want to know
where it came from.
Mr. Data,
see if there is any mention
of a Jason Vigo
in Federation records.
You might start
with Miranda Vigo.
She was born on New Gaul
about 50 years ago.
Aye, sir.
Number one,
contact the Ferengi government.
Find out
all you can about Bok.
He was wearing
a daimon's uniform.
If he has regained his rank,
I want to know why.
( door chimes )
Come.
The Ferengi
government
is debating an amendment
to the Rules of Acquisition.
It could be a while
before we hear from them.
Data found out that
the woman you mentioned
has a son
named Jason.
This is the most recent
picture we could find.
( sighs )
How old is
the boy now?
Twenty-three.
He and his mother left Earth
12 years ago.
They settled on Camor V.
That's all we know.
The planet's records
are virtually nonexistent.
Picard to Bridge.
Set a course for
the Camor System,
warp five.
Aye, sir.
Will...
I do appreciate
your not asking
but I do think you have
a right to know.
There is a possibility
that the boy is my son.
I was involved with his mother
for a short time about...
well, 24 years ago.
We met through a friend
when I was on shore leave
on Earth.
It was, uh...
all very romantic,
very intense,
probably because we both knew
that I would be leaving
in two weeks.
And we kept
in touch for a while,
but we never managed
to get together again.
She never said anything
to you about being pregnant?
No.
So either Bok is wrong,
and I'm not the father,
or Miranda decided
to raise the child alone.
Which, quite frankly,
wouldn't surprise me.
She was
very independent...
very strong-willed.
She would have to be
to get by on Camor V.
But whether he's my son
or not, he is in danger.
Bok tried to kill me six years
ago and I don't doubt
that he will try to make good
his threat against the boy.
Anything?
There are no Ferengi vessels
within range of our scanners.
Captain, I am unable
to find any information
on Jason Vigo's
current whereabouts.
What about
his mother?
No, sir.
Miranda was trained
as a botanist.
She always used to talk
about running a farm one day.
Maybe we should concentrate
on the agricultural areas.
That would significantly
narrow our search.
The only cultivated land is
on the southern continent
and there are relatively
few people engaged
in agricultural
activities.
There cannot be many
non-Camorites among them.
Scan for
human life signs.
DATA:
I am detecting eight humans.
Three are female.
However, they are all too young
to be Miranda Vigo.
What about males?
One is an infant.
Another
is elderly.
Two are middle-aged.
That's seven.
You said there were eight.
I am having difficulty getting
a clear reading on the eighth.
The individual appears to be
approximately two kilometers
beneath the
planet's surface.
Male or female?
Male.
Between 20 and 30 years old.
No one in their
right mind
would go that far
underground alone.
Unless he were
forced to.
Captain, I am reading seismic
instability in the area.
He is in danger.
Relay his coordinates
to the transporter room.
Have them beam him
aboard.
DATA:
Aye, sir.
( whoosh of active transport )
What the...?
This is a
Federation ship.
That's right.
I'm Captain Picard,
Jean-Luc Picard.
I realize I wasn't supposed
to be spelunking that cave,
but don't you have
something better to do?
We thought
you were at risk.
Oh.
Well, I wasn't.
So maybe you should just
beam me back where I was.
Are you Jason Vigo?
I, uh...
I know him.
Is he in trouble?
In a manner
of speaking.
Someone has made a threat
against his life.
Jason,
I'm an old friend
of your mother's.
I'm here
because you're in danger.
Why would anybody
want to kill me?
The person
who has made the threat
is under the impression
that you...
are my son.
Am I?
I don't know.
My mother never told me
who my father was--
just that he
was in Starfleet.
Maybe we should
contact her.
She, uh... she died
a few years ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Jason, I think
it's important
that we find out
one way or the other.
Would you be willing
to permit a genetic test?
If I'm not your son,
is this person still
going to want to kill me?
I doubt it.
In that case, you
won't mind my saying
that I hope you're
not my father.
What were you doing
in the caves, Jason?
Are you
a seismologist?
No, I just
enjoy climbing.
Without an antigrav
harness?
No, they get
in the way.
So,
what do you do?
Um... I'm between jobs
right now.
I see.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
The test results are ready
if you'd like to hear them.
Your genetic code
is a cross between the DNA
of your mother, Miranda Vigo,
and your father,
Jean-Luc Picard.
What's all this?
Oh, these are
archaeological fragments
that I've collected
over the years.
This is
a Silvan glyph stone.
And, um, this is...
This is a Gorlan
prayer stick.
It's really
quite rare.
Is it valuable?
Oh, not really.
Only to students
of archaeology such as myself.
Though, I did have
to hand over a bottle
of very old Saurian brandy
for it.
I'd say you got taken.
Well, perhaps.
But it's of value
to me nonetheless.
On Camor, something has value
if you can eat it or sell it.
Everything else
is luxury.
Would you like
some tea?
No... thanks.
Something else?
No.
Tea, Earl Grey,
hot.
I'm sure that
this whole thing
is as much of a surprise
to you as it is to me.
I really want to be
honest with you, Jason.
I only knew your mother
for a very short time.
I-I would have liked
to have known her better...
It just didn't
work out that way.
You look a lot
like her, you know.
It's the eyes,
I think.
I would like to make one
thing clear, Jason.
Your mother
never told me about you.
If she had, I would have
been part of your life.
Maybe that's not
what she wanted.
I think I'd like to go back
to the surface now.
I think it would be better
if you stayed on board
the Enterprise
until we have resolved
this situation with Bok.
What is this situation
with Bok, anyway?
I mean, why does
he want me dead?
Years ago, I was forced
to destroy a starship
commanded
by his son.
Bok apparently feels that
it would be fitting vengeance
to kill my son.
Well, I can't
hide forever.
Of course not.
We are trying
to locate Bok now.
I want to confront him,
settle this matter.
How long is this
going to take?
I assure you, there is
no one more eager
to put this behind us
than I am.
Where do I stay?
We'll get you
some quarters.
Okay, let's go.
Jason...
Your being here...
I hope it will give us
the chance to get
to know each other.
We've managed to shut down
the probe's power system,
so we could beam it aboard,
but it's not going
to be easy to figure out
where this thing
came from.
Bok took the precaution
of encrypting the probe's
navigational systems
so that we would be unable
to decipher its flight path.
We ran an analysis
of the probe's hull.
From the energy signatures
and the particle
deposits we found,
it looks like it traveled
through a dichromic nebula,
was exposed to an intensive
gravimetric distortion,
and passed within
one light year of
a Class-4 pulsar.
Those phenomena
are relatively common.
We would need to identify
at least one of them
specifically
in order to postulate
a flight path.
Understood.
Captain, incoming message
from Daimon Birta.
Put it on screen.
Thank you for taking the time
to talk with us, Daimon.
I understand
you have a problem.
Yes, it concerns
Daimon Bok.
Bok is no Daimon.
He was relieved of command
six years ago.
He was unstable,
dangerous.
We had to confine him
to Rog prison.
But he's
no longer there.
He was able to buy himself out
about two years ago.
I see.
Do you know
his whereabouts now?
I understand he was seen
in the Dorias Cluster
not too long ago.
But that cluster consists
of more than 20 star systems.
( chuckling )
You don't have
to thank me, Captain.
LA FORGE:
Believe it or not, Captain,
that might have given us
the fix we need.
There's a nebula
in the Dorias Cluster
that matches the same
particle signature
we found
on the probe.
There is a Class-4 pulsar
three light-years
from the nebula.
My calculations indicate
the probe was launched
in the Xendi Kabu system.
Plot a course,
take us out of orbit.
Jean-Luc, come in.
I think I need to talk
to a parent.
So, what's he like?
I'm not sure that
I can tell you.
He puts up so
many barriers.
I have no idea
what is underneath.
Keep in mind
he's had 20 years
to be angry that
his father wasn't there.
It's going to take some time
to get over those feelings
but I do think
it's possible.
Perhaps.
But surely it would be wrong
to force the issue.
My sense is
that he is
a very independent
young man.
Perhaps it would be best
if I left him alone.
Let him come to me
if he wants to.
Maybe you're right.
But I think
you should consider this.
Are you doing the best thing
for Jason
or what's easiest for you?
( door chimes )
Yeah.
Hello, Jason.
I'm Deanna Troi,
ship's counselor.
Come in.
Did Captain Picard
ask you to come talk to me?
No, I just thought I'd come
and see how you were doing.
A lot's happened
in the last few hours.
I thought you might like
to talk about it.
I'll be all right.
People have wanted
to kill me before.
But you've never met
your father before.
And I have to admit,
I never thought I would.
It must be somewhat
overwhelming.
I'm a
little shaky.
Well, that's
only natural.
But you know what?
I feel better already
just talking to you.
So, how did you feel
about the captain?
About your father?
He's okay.
A little stiff.
But where are you from?
I was born
on Betazed.
Do all the women there
have eyes like yours?
Look, Jason, I came here
to talk to you
because
I'm the ship's counselor.
If you don't want
to talk to me in that way
then I think I should go.
Fine.
You're welcome
to make an appointment
to come to my office.
Maybe I'll do just that.
BOK:
Picard, can you hear me?
I will kill him,
Picard,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
Security to Captain's quarters
immediately.
Our shields were up.
How could he have
beamed through them?
I'm not sure
he did.
Sensors don't show
any sign of an intruder.
Could it have been
another hologram?
I don't think so,
Captain.
Something has
to generate a hologram.
We would have
detected it.
Bok once used a
mind-control device
to make me hallucinate.
That device emitted a very
specific energy signature.
I'm not reading
anything like that.
Could he have modified
the device
so he could use it
without being detected?
It's possible.
I'll recalibrate
the sensors
to scan for low-intensity
transmissions
and just to be sure,
I'll sweep your quarters
with a resonance
scanner.
Good.
Keep me posted.
Mr. Worf, I want you to assign
a security detail to Jason.
And what
about yourself?
I am not the target
of Bok's threats.
Jason is.
Captain, I have compiled
all available records
pertaining to Jason Vigo's
criminal record.
Criminal record?
Yes, sir.
He has been charged
three times with petty theft,
twice for disorderly conduct
and several dozen times
with trespassing.
Trespassing?
I believe the charges relate
to his climbing activities
in the caves beneath
the planet's surface.
This is the information
you requested, is it not?
Thank you,
Mr. Data.
What was
your name again?
Lieutenant Rhodes.
Actually... I meant
your first name.
Sandra.
Well, Sandra,
Do you think you could...
give me some room?
We're supposed to be
keeping an eye on you.
Can't you keep an eye on me
from over there?
( sighs )
PICARD:
Good morning.
I thought you said
your ship was the safest
place I could be.
Why the guards?
Because Bok appeared
in my quarters last night.
Now, it might not
have been him.
It may have been an image.
We're investigating.
Look, why don't you just
drop me off somewhere?
I can watch out
for myself.
That wouldn't be wise.
I've been doing it
since I was 15.
I'm sure you have, but Bok
is a dangerous creature.
He has a starship,
he has technology--
All right, all right.
I'll stay here.
You seem to like
rock climbing.
The holodeck can create
some very challenging climbs.
We could
go down together
and I could show you
how to use the program.
Thanks, but, uh, I think
I can figure it out myself.
Perhaps we could
climb together.
I'm probably not as...
skilled as you
but I'm not inexperienced.
Look...
I'm sorry.
I appreciate what
you're trying to do
but, Captain...
Captain?
Father? Jean-Luc?
I don't know what I'm
supposed to call you.
As soon as this thing
with Bok is over,
I'm leaving.
So, don't you see?
There really isn't any point
in our getting acquainted.
Let me know as soon
as you catch him, all right?
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47829.1.
We've been in the Xendi Kabu
system for over three hours
and still no sign of Bok.
Captain, I am detecting
an object 5,000 kilometers
off our starboard bow.
It is
another probe.
Why didn't we
detect it before?
It must have
been cloaked, sir.
It came out
of nowhere.
On screen.
Is it another
holographic device?
I do not believe so.
Captain, the probe's systems
are overloading.
Red alert!
Shields up.
Damage report.
No damage,
sir.
Captain, I do not believe
it was meant as an attack
but rather
as a message.
A message?
Yes sir, in B'zal,
a Ferengi code
which uses alternating patterns
of light
and darkness.
Can you
translate it?
I am attempting to do so.
The message reads:
"My revenge
is at hand."
He's proved that he can
get to us whenever he wants.
Why doesn't he
do something?
Tea, Earl Grey, hot.
If you want me
to stay and talk
you better not call
for security this time.
How do you like your boy,
Captain?
Is he everything
you'd always hoped for?
It's a risky game
you're playing, coming here.
Next time, we'll be
ready for you.
Why don't we settle
this now?
Oh... and how do you
propose to do that, Picard?
You murdered my son!
It was self-defense--
he fired on my ship.
You were in
Ferengi space!
I didn't know that.
If he'd told me,
I would have withdrawn.
I'm sorry, but there's nothing
I can do to bring him back.
How touching.
Your apology is
worthless to me.
I demand that
you repay me for my loss.
You cannot put
a price on a life.
Oh, but you can,
Picard.
You can pay me
with your son's life.
No.
You don't have
any choice!
I insist on being paid.
That should do it.
Let's run a level-3
bio-scan just to be sure.
Rhodes to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency,
deck nine, section four.
Let's go.
Have you had
any other seizures
like this before?
No,
not really.
Sometimes my hand shakes,
but never this bad.
When did it first
start to happen?
About
a few months ago.
Do you have any idea
what's wrong with me?
You have a condition called
the Forrester-Trent syndrome.
It's a degenerative
neurological disorder--
very rare.
What do you mean,
degenerative?
If it goes
untreated,
it could result in
paralysis, even death.
I'm going to start you on a
neuro-stabilization regimen.
If we're lucky, it will
halt the degeneration
and maybe reverse
its effects.
The disease
is hereditary.
I know your father
doesn't have it.
Was your mother prone
to these seizures?
Not that I know of.
There have been
some cases reported
where the disease
was instigated
by a random mutation.
I'll run a
micro-cellular scan
and see if that's
what happened.
In the meantime,
I want you to try
to take it easy
and get some rest.
(scoffs)
Is he going
to be all right?
I wish I could say
for certain.
But I'm not sure how he'll
respond to treatments.
I've been thinking about what
you said the other day, and...
You know,
I think you were right.
I had convinced myself
that Jason didn't want me
to reach out to him.
You know, I don't think
anyone is born
knowing how
to be a parent.
You just sort of
figure it out as you go,
but the one quality
that tends to be
a requirement
for parenthood is patience.
Well, I'm not sure that
that is going to be enough.
I found out that...
Jason has
a criminal record.
It's nothing
very serious.
It's only petty theft
and so forth,
but I can't help feeling
that if I had been
part of his life
then he wouldn't be
so troubled now.
Maybe, but why waste time
blaming yourself
for not being there?
Just be here for him now.
And be patient?
And be patient.
We think we've found
something, Captain.
Bok was in direct contact
with this chair
for an extended period.
It is showing a
distinctive subspace
signature as a result.
We think he's
using some kind of
subspace transporter
to beam aboard
the Enterprise.
My understanding is that
such devices were impractical.
The Federation abandoned
its research in the field
because the technology was
found to be unreliable,
as well as
energy intensive.
In order to transport matter
through subspace,
you have to put it
in a state of quantum flux.
It's very unstable.
What range would that kind
of transporter have?
In theory, it could operate
over several light years.
That means that the probe
that exploded
could have been beamed
into position
from some point
outside sensor range.
If Bok uses
his transporter again,
we might be able to trace
the subspace signature
and locate his ship.
Is there any way
we can we keep Bok
from beaming aboard
the Enterprise again?
I don't think there is.
See, if he has the ability
to beam aboard
he may be able
to beam someone away.
It is a possibility.
I'm concerned that he may try
to take Jason.
Is there any way
we can protect him?
You know, we might be able
to keep a signal lock on him
at all times.
If Bok tries to beam him away,
we might be able
to hold him here.
In order to do so,
we would need to tie
the ship's subspace field coils
into the transporter system.
Make it so.
Computer, where is Jason Vigo?
Jason Vigo is
in holodeck four.
( grunts )
Would you wait outside?
( door opens, closes )
Not bad.
I like climbing.
There's something
about
actually having your fate
in your own hands.
Yeah, I know.
It looks as though
we may have found out
how to locate
Bok's ship.
This could all
soon be over.
You came all the way up
here just to tell me that?
I thought it would
make you feel better.
Thanks.
That was nice of you.
Jason, when your mother
and I parted,
I lost track
of her completely.
But I would like to know more
about what happened to her,
if you wouldn't mind
telling me.
Like what?
Well, how did you
end up on Camor?
It's an unlikely place
for a woman and child.
Well, you know
how she was--
See a stray cat,
take it in.
See somebody cold,
give them your coat.
Yes, that was Miranda,
all right.
She'd heard about
all the children
that had been
orphaned on Camor
from the Cardassian war.
Oh... I see.
I was only ten
when we went there.
I remember her
telling me
all about the
boys and girls
that didn't have anyone
to care for them.
So she got this big house,
practically falling apart
then she started
rounding up children.
Eventually, there were
over 40 of us there.
She called it a school.
You know, she got up
before dawn every day
and went to bed
well after midnight.
In between, she never
stopped working.
She taught us all
how to read.
And she grew vegetables
in hardpan to feed us.
And she made sure
we knew how to sing.
It's important in
a place like Camor.
And then one day,
she was attacked
by two men in the street
in broad daylight
for the food
she was carrying.
And if she'd just
given it to them,
they probably
wouldn't have hurt her.
But she knew how important
the food was to us.
So they killed her.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be sorry for me.
My mother made sure
that we were all
tough enough to make it.
Jason, isn't there some way
that I can be a father to you?
My own father and I
were estranged.
He wanted me
to stay at home
and tend the vineyards,
and I wanted
to join Starfleet.
And he died before we could
come to terms with that,
and I've regretted that
all of my life.
I don't want the same thing
to happen to you and me.
You don't understand.
I'm not anybody
you'd want for a son.
Trust me,
if you knew...
if you knew
anything about me,
you wouldn't,
you wouldn't be trying so hard.
You're so wrong.
Oh, really?
Let me spell it out
for you.
I've been in trouble
since I was a teenager.
I lie.
I steal.
I use people.
I'm
a criminal.
That's what
your son is.
I know.
You do?
Oh, yes.
I know all about your troubles
with the Camor authorities.
You do?
It doesn't make
any difference, Jason.
You're still my son.
And like it or not,
I'm your father.
I don't know
what that means.
I know it means
something.
There's some
connection.
Yeah.
But one thing
is clear--
You'll never look at your
hairline again in the same way.
You wanted
to see me?
Yes.
It's about Jason.
I finished the micro-cellular
scan I was running.
There's something
you need to know.
Sir, sensors
are detecting
a subspace carrier wave
headed for the ship.
Its signature is consistent
with Bok's transporter.
See if you can trace it
and locate Bok's ship.
Geordi, are you ready
down there?
I've got
a signal lock on Jason.
Riker to Picard.
Picard here.
Bok is trying
to use his transporter.
The transporter beam is focusing
on deck nine, section four.
Jason's quarters.
LA FORGE:
I'm on it, Commander.
RHODES:
Security to Bridge.
Bok is beaming Jason
off the ship.
Initiating
transport now.
I'm losing his signal.
Bok is reestablishing
his lock on him.
Have you been able
to locate Bok's ship?
No, sir.
The subspace signature
left by his transporter
is decaying more
rapidly than predicted.
It may not be
possible to trace it.
WORF:
Captain, another probe
has materialized
500 kilometers
to starboard.
It is sending
a transmission.
Put it on screen.
This is
a very special day, Picard.
15 years ago you took
my son away from me.
Today, I will take your son
away from you.
It will be our anniversary.
I wanted you to see
him one last time.
DATA:
I am tracing
the transporter beam
Bok used to send the probe.
The ship
is holding position
approximately 300 billion
kilometers from here.
Plot a course.
Maximum warp.
Even at warp nine,
we wouldn't get there
for another
20 minutes.
The modifications you made
to the transporter--
Is there any way
we could use
a subspace transport
from here
to get me
onto Bok's ship?
It may be possible, sir,
but it would not be advisable.
I'll take that as a yes.
You're with me.
There.
I've aligned
the field coils.
Phase dampers
are in sync.
Standing by to modulate
the transport pattern.
Captain, we might be able
to get you over there
but I don't see how
we're going to get you back.
We'll deal with that
when the time comes.
Transport's going to take
longer than normal.
We'll have to shunt
your pattern
through the subspace
field coils.
Understood.
Initiating transport
sequence now.
Maybe we can
make a deal.
What kind of deal?
Tell my father
you killed me.
Put a phaser burn
on my shirt
and send it to him.
He'll think
I'm dead.
That's what this
is about, isn't it?
I got friends
on Camor V
that will make it
worth your while.
I understand your
desire to live,
but I want Picard
to see your body
so there will
be no doubt.
Lower your weapons
or Bok is dead.
Lower yours,
or your son dies!
You know as well as I do, Bok,
he's not my son.
I know
what you've done.
Miranda Vigo
is his mother,
but I am not
his father.
You made it appear so because
you re-sequenced his DNA,
but your technique
was flawed.
He developed
a neurological disorder.
When my ship's doctor
investigated it,
she discovered
what you had done.
Now he'll never
pay the ransom.
Shut up!
There never was
a ransom.
All he was ever interested in
was vengeance.
Daimon, is this true?
He's not
a daimon!
He was stripped
of command.
They had no right
to do that to me.
He lied to you, so that you
would help him in his plan.
The Enterprise is closing in
on your position.
If you let the two of us go,
they won't attack you.
They won't attack us
with you on board.
They will cripple your ship
and keep you here
until the Ferengi
authorities arrive.
You've got
a lot of explaining to do.
Your only hope
is to turn Bok over to them
and tell them
that he deceived you.
There is no profit
in this for us.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47831.8.
At Jason's request
the Enterprise has returned
to Camor V.
Dr. Crusher feels
I'm responding well
to the treatment.
She thinks that the damage
may be completely reversed.
I'm glad to hear it.
Yeah.
Are you sure that you
wouldn't like to stay
on board the Enterprise
for a few more days?
Uh, I can't.
I have a life
back on Camor.
It's a mess, but I'd
like to go back
and straighten
things out.
I understand.
Well, uh, maybe next time
you come back this way
you can look me up.
I will.
I, uh, put
a little something
into your bag while
you were packing.
I know you would
probably have preferred
a bottle
of Saurian brandy
but, uh, that's all
I could come up with.
I-I can't
accept this.
I want you to have it.
Energize.