Graves at my command
have wak'd their sleepers.
Op'd, and let 'em forth
by my so potent art.
But this rough magic
I here abjure,
and when I have requir'd
some heavenly music--
which even now I do--
to work mine end
upon their senses
that this airy charm
is for,
I'll break my staff,
bury it certain fathoms
in the earth,
and deeper
than did ever plummet sound,
I'll...
Captain?
Sir, your attention
is wandering.
Data, I can
barely see you.
But, sir, I am supposed
to be attempting
a Neoplatonic
magical rite.
The darkness
is appropriate
for such a ritual.
Yes, but, Data,
this is a play.
The audience
has to see you.
Hmm.
Perhaps I have been
too literal
with respect
to my set design.
Computer,
modify holodeck program
Data 7-3, Shakespeare's
The Tempest,
Act Five, Scene One.
Increase torch
light by... 20%.
There, that's
much better.
Now, do you want
to try it again?
Yes, sir.
Captain, I am not certain
I fully understand
this Prospero character.
I would appreciate any
insight you might have
that would improve
my performance.
Well, Data,
Shakespeare was witnessing
the end of
the Renaissance
and the birth
of the modern era,
and Prospero
finds himself
in a world
where his powers
are no longer needed.
So, we see him here
about to perform
one final creative act
before giving up
his art forever.
Hmm. There is
certainly
a tragic aspect
to the character.
Yes, but there's a--
( distant train whistles )
a certain expectancy, too,
um, a hopefulness
about the future.
You see, Shakespeare enjoyed
mixing opposites--
the past and--
and the future,
hope and despair...
Data, what is this?
Is this part
of your program?
( train whistling )
DATA: No, sir.
Well, what is going on?
It appears to be
a steam locomotive.
A train?
If I am not mistaken.
Computer, end program.
( train chugging closer )
Computer,
end program!
( train whistle blowing )
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Captain?
You are injured.
Oh, yes, I know.
It's all right.
I will get it seen to,
Data.
The train we encountered
was from one of Dr. Crusher's
holodeck programs.
It was a re-creation
of the Orient Express,
a train which traveled
from Paris to Istanbul
from the late
19th century...
Yes, yes, Data, I know
about the Orient Express,
but what is it doing
on Prospero's island?
There appears to have
been a malfunction
in the holodeck's database
retrieval program.
The two programs somehow
temporarily linked together.
Is it possible
that this malfunction
would affect
the other holodecks as well?
It is a possibility.
I will need to run
a full diagnostic
to be certain.
Very good, Data,
but shut down
the other holodecks as well
until you're finished,
just to be on
the safe side.
Aye, sir.
I never realized that you
were interested in trains.
Are you aware that,
at its peak,
the Orient Express carried
more than 10,000 people a year?
It isn't really
the train itself
that I'm interested in.
What then?
It's the experience.
The Orient Express is
romantic, mysterious.
It's an elegant way
to see exotic places
and meet
fascinating people.
Do you know that,
one time, on one trip,
both Sigmund Freud
and Gertrude Stein
just happened to be
in the same car?
They ended up having dinner
together every night.
I wonder what
they talked about?
Why don't you take a trip
yourself and find out?
RIKER:
Riker to Picard.
Picard here.
All sections ready
to begin the survey, sir.
Very good.
I'm on my way.
Thank you.
Don't forget the trip,
Jean-Luc, think about it.
You never know who you'll meet
on the Orient Express.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47869.2.
After weathering an unexpected
magnascopic storm
in the Mekorda sector,
we are continuing our search
for new Federation
colony sites.
I don't think
there's any possibility
of developing sites
in this region.
Most of the stars are
main sequence binaries.
There are no M-class
planets.
Well, let's move on
to another survey region.
Have stellar
cartography begin a...
Mr. Data, report.
The ship has moved
into warp, sir.
RIKER:
Who gave that command?
Apparently, no one.
Helm and navigation controls
are not functioning.
Our speed is now
warp 7.3 and holding.
Picard
to Engineering.
Mr. La Forge,
what's going on?
We've lost primary helm
control on the Bridge.
I don't understand it.
The impulse systems
suddenly cut out,
and the warp drive just
kicked in.
RIKER:
Geordi, can you take
the engines offline?
I'm working on it.
Mr. Data,
what's our heading?
Bearing 187
mark 4, sir.
I am unable to determine
our destination.
However, we are moving away
from the Mekorda sector.
LA FORGE:
Captain, the computer's locked
out all the propulsion controls.
I can't access
any of the overrides.
If you want us to stop,
I'll have to do
an emergency core shutdown.
That would leave us
without warp power
for more than a week.
Begin the procedure,
Mr. La Forge.
We are no longer
at warp, sir.
Impulse power
has resumed.
All systems
show normal.
Where are we?
We are approximately
30 billion kilometers
from our original
position.
Well done,
Mr. La Forge.
It wasn't me.
I didn't have time to complete
the shutdown procedure.
PICARD:
Well, I want an explanation,
Mr. La Forge.
Picard out.
Have you found anything yet?
Only that we seem to have
more than one mystery here.
We still don't know why
the ship jumped into warp,
but it looks like
we're lucky that it did.
There was a theta
flux distortion
building up
around the ship.
Why didn't
our sensors alert us?
Well, our sensors
were never designed
to detect theta flux
distortions,
and, yet, there is
a record of the distortion
in our sensor log.
That's the other
mystery.
One fact is clear,
however.
The distortion was
growing in strength.
If we had remained
at our original position
1.7 seconds longer,
the distortion would have
ruptured our warp core.
If the Enterprise hadn't
jumped into warp when it did,
we would have been
blown to pieces.
I don't get it, Data.
What would cause the engines
to suddenly jump into warp?
Perhaps the engines
were activated
by a random
power fluctuation.
Which occurred
just in time
to save the ship?
It is improbable,
but it is possible.
I don't know,
I don't think I'm ready
to start
believing in luck.
There is another
possibility.
Yeah?
What's that?
The sensors
apparently detected
a dangerous anomaly that
threatened the Enterprise.
It is possible
that they triggered
a safety device
that caused the ship
to avoid
destruction.
Yeah, but there's
no direct link
between the warp engines
and the sensors.
Whoa, what is that?
It looks like some kind
of new circuit node,
and it's connected
to at least...
half a dozen points
on the sensor array.
It appears to be connected
to several other systems
as well, including
the warp control circuits.
Well, I guess there's
a connection between
the warp engines
and the sensors after all.
A force field.
Where did that
come from?
I am not certain.
Perhaps it came
from the node itself.
Well, wherever
it came from,
it sure doesn't want us
messing with this node.
It appears to be
protecting itself.
We found these nodes
in several systems
around the ship.
At some level
or another,
they're all connected.
These nodes were
linking the sensors
to our warp control
and defensive systems.
We believe this is why
the ship jumped to warp.
When the sensors
detected danger,
the defensive system
reacted to the threat
and activated
the warp engines
to protect us.
Where did the nodes
come from?
It is possible
the magnascopic storm
we recently
encountered had
an unexpected effect
on the ship's systems.
Wherever they come from,
they seem to be multiplying.
As they increase,
it will become
progressively more difficult
to control the ship.
What do you propose
we do?
Well, getting rid of them
isn't going to be so easy.
When we attempted
to examine the circuitry
of one of the nodes,
it generated a force field
to keep us out.
Well, whatever's going on,
our first priority
is getting back
control of the ship.
Agreed.
All of the nodal
connections intersect
in Holodeck Three.
It appears to be
a focal point of some kind.
We might be able to find a way
to use the holodeck's circuitry
to disable
the nodes permanently.
All right,
let's do it.
Commander, the holodeck
appears to be in operation.
I thought you shut down
the entire system.
I did, but it has
reactivated itself,
and it will not
disengage.
Which program is
running?
Several different programs
are running simultaneously.
This should be
interesting.
( train wheels rumbling )
( spurs jingling )
You weren't kidding,
Mr. Data.
No, sir.
I estimate that
this... scene
consists of portions
of seven distinct
holodeck programs.
See if you can
access the circuits
that have been
affected by the nodes.
( train whistle blows )
Tickets.
Tickets, please.
Please have
your tickets ready.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, madam.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Tickets, please.
You know, I never even
been away from home.
Now I'm going all the way
to Vertiform City.
Very nice, sir.
Enjoy your trip.
Tickets, please.
Tickets?
Thank you, sir.
Tickets, please.
DATA:
Commander?
Tickets.
I've located a large
concentration of nodes
behind this wall.
They appear to be
connected directly
to the holodeck's
main power coupling.
All right, go ahead
and depolarize
the entire power grid.
The power grid is located
beneath this deck, sir.
CONDUCTOR:
Get away from there!
Would you gentlemen care
to show me your tickets?
I believe we left our tickets
in our compartments.
Mr. Worf, I told you
to bring the tickets.
I, uh, forgot.
I don't think you folks
belong on this train.
MAN:
Hold it!
You leave these
people alone.
They're only
trying to help.
You go back
to the engine.
This doesn't concern you.
They're all trying
to hijack the train.
Hey, if you're
the engineer,
who's doing
the driving?
( gunshot )
I am.
Easy, sir, easy.
I got you.
I'm all right.
Thanks.
Looks like the navigational
relay's overloaded.
( bell ringing )
PICARD:
Geordi, what's going on?
We just went
into warp.
We've lost engine and helm
control again, Captain,
but this time...
they're completely burned out.
I don't know if we can
stop the ship.
I believe we have
changed direction.
Now we're on
the right track.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are on our way.
( cheering )
I was right.
He was trying
to make off with my brick.
Take good care
of that.
We can't afford
to lose it.
Now, are you people
going to leave,
or do we have to throw you
off the train?
Commander.
According
to my tricorder,
the holodeck safeties
have been disengaged.
His weapon
could be lethal.
All right,
let's get out of here.
The number of systems now
being affected by the nodes
has increased
considerably.
Sensors, engines,
replicators, propulsion--
they're all
working together now,
almost independently
of the main computer,
and the nodes link them all
through the holodeck.
But why the holodeck?
It doesn't make any sense.
Commander, I believe
what happens on the holodeck
has a direct effect
on the ship.
When we attempted
to destroy the nodes,
the characters
on the train
responded
almost immediately
to stop us.
And when the engineer
tried to protect us,
one of the other
characters shot him.
Then the conductor
signaled for the train
to change direction...
and, at approximately
the same time...
The Enterprise also took off
in a new direction.
Are you saying the ship
is under the control
of the holodeck?
Not precisely.
Geordi...
does the configuration
of connection nodes
look familiar to you?
Yeah.
Yeah, it looks
a little like
the structure of your
positronic brain.
DATA:
That is correct.
It would appear that
the nodes are in the process
of creating a rudimentary
neural net.
Data...
what are you suggesting?
Unlikely
as it may sound,
I believe
the Enterprise
may be forming
an intelligence.
This is a synaptic map
of the human neocortex.
This is a cross-section
of my positronic net.
And this is a schematic
of the connection nodes
linking
the ship's systems.
I believe some sort
of neural matrix
is forming on the ship.
It is still
relatively primitive,
but it is
an intelligence,
nonetheless.
How could
that happen?
I believe it is
an emergent property.
Explain.
Complex systems can
sometimes behave in ways
that are entirely
unpredictable.
The human brain,
for example,
might be described in terms
of cellular functions
and neurochemical
interactions.
But that description
does not explain
human consciousness,
a capacity that far exceeds
simple neural functions.
Consciousness is
an emergent property.
In other words,
something that's more than
just the sum of its parts.
DATA:
Exactly.
How does that explain
what's happening
to the Enterprise?
The Enterprise contains
a vast database
of information
which is managed
by a sophisticated
computer.
This complex system
gives the ship many
of the characteristics
of a biological
organism.
That's true-- it sees
with its sensors,
and it talks with
its communications systems.
In a sense,
it almost reproduces
with the replicators.
And you think that
the ship has somehow
gone beyond
these functions.
It's developing
a new capacity.
Yes, sir, I believe
a self-determining
intelligence is emerging.
If that is so,
what does the ship want?
Where is it taking us?
I believe the key
to understanding
the ship's behavior
lies in the holodeck.
All of the connection nodes
intersect at that location.
It is clearly some kind
of processing center.
Processing center?
Yes, sir.
A focal point
where all the ideas
and instincts
of this emerging
intelligence
are first expressed
in some form.
Almost like
an imagination.
Captain, I'd like to go
to the holodeck.
I could interact
with the characters
and maybe find
some clues
to help us understand
what's happening.
Very well.
Mr. Data, Mr. Worf,
I want you to go along.
See if you can reestablish
control of the ship
without damaging
the nodes.
If the ship is truly
an emerging intelligence,
then we have
a responsibility
to treat it with the same
respect as any other being.
Welcome aboard,
Counselor.
If you will distract
these people,
I will attempt
to depolarize
the power grid.
( bell clanging )
Excuse me.
Have you finished
the puzzle yet?
Not yet,
but we're getting close.
WORF:
Do you recognize it?
No.
WORF:
I would like to help.
Tell me, what exactly
are you making?
What do you think
we're making? A puzzle.
No. No, I meant
the picture.
What is it?
Well, I don't know.
Can you deal me in?
Sorry.
It's a two-man game.
Hey!
Get your hand
off of that.
Is that why
you killed the engineer?
To get this brick?
I had to get it back.
You know what
it's worth, lady?
Plenty.
And I got to get it
to Keystone City.
Why? What's at
Keystone City?
It's where
everything begins.
Gin.
Are you succeeding,
Commander?
I am ready to access
the main power grid.
Keystone City,
next stop.
Keystone City.
Well...
look who's back.
We do not want
any trouble.
We are simply...
passengers.
Well, then I'm sure
you wouldn't mind
showing me
your tickets.
Right.
Sorry, boys.
You're getting off
right here.
This is my stop.
Wait. What happens
at Keystone City?
Why are you taking
the brick there?
Excuse me.
I think we should
follow that man.
That brick might be
an important clue.
Where did he go?
( electronic whirring )
( beeping )
I can access
the power grid here.
I will attempt
to depolarize the grid
by using a low-frequency
inversion field.
It may disengage the nodes
without destroying them.
TROI:
There he is.
I'm going after him.
( car approaching )
( dog barking )
What are you doing here?
Laying the foundation.
Now if youse
will excuse me,
I got a train to catch.
I don't understand it,
Captain.
All of a sudden, Cargo Bay Five
started to depressurize.
Did everyone
get out in time?
Yes, sir, and
I've reestablished
the containment field,
but I'm reading
massive power surges
in the cargo bay
and all sorts
of transporter activity--
Something weird is
happening there, Captain.
I want you to send a team
down there immediately.
Find out
what's going on.
Aye, sir.
La Forge to Bridge.
Picard here.
What's going on?
I wish I could tell you.
That man said he was
laying a foundation.
A foundation for what?
Troi to Data.
Data here.
How are you doing?
I encountered
a minor difficulty,
Counselor, but it has
been dealt with.
( engine revving )
I am ready to depolarize
the power grid.
It looks like
the ship's replicator
and transporter systems
have been merged somehow
to create this.
The question is,
what is it?
Ensign, I want you
to run a full
spectral analysis
on this...
( rumbling )
I'm reading massive
power fluctuations.
The ship is losing
its structural integrity.
What's happening?
It's an earthquake.
La Forge to Data.
Stop what you're doing.
Acknowledged.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Data, I think
we ought to get together
and compare notes.
DATA:
Agreed.
The ship was
protecting itself again--
stopping us
from interfering.
Whatever it's doing,
it intends to continue.
I'm betting that all this
has something to do
with that object that's
forming in the cargo bay.
I think he's right,
Captain.
Look at the common themes
playing out on the holodeck--
a puzzle being
put together,
a foundation
being laid,
a paper doll
being fashioned.
They're all images of
something being constructed.
LA FORGE:
And some kind of object
in the cargo bay that's being
constructed atom by atom.
What is that object?
LA FORGE:
I have no idea,
but it's composed
of silica polymers,
duranium, and a couple
of other compounds
we haven't been able
to identify yet.
But creating it has had quite
an effect on our systems.
Warp power has
dropped 47%.
Counselor, did you draw
any other conclusions
from your experiences
on the holodeck?
Anything that would
help us to understand
this situation?
The holodeck was full
of metaphoric imagery,
like it was having
some kind of daydream.
It may not make
literal sense,
but symbolically
it probably does
have some kind
of logic to it.
These characters
you spoke to,
do they have
any significance?
I think they represent
different aspects of the ship.
The engineer,
for instance,
may represent
the navigational system.
The gunslinger could be
the weapon system.
Is there any way that
we can persuade them
to give us back
control of the ship?
I don't think it's possible
to reason with them.
Many of them are genuinely
unaware of what's going on.
It's as though this
emergent intelligence
is like an infant--
acting on impulse,
trying to figure
itself out as it goes.
The only source of experience
it can draw on is ours,
through our
holodeck programs.
Then, is there
a way that we can
relate to them
on their own level?
Find some way to
influence their behavior?
Maybe there is.
I'd like to go back
and try.
Counselor,
we haven't been able
to reestablish
the safeties.
The injuries you suffered
on the holodeck,
weren't severe,
but next time
they might kill you.
I'm aware of that.
Very well, Counselor.
Go ahead, but bear in mind
that whenever we have tried
to hinder their efforts,
we've failed.
Perhaps it's time
to cooperate with them.
You don't belong
on this train.
Three tickets
for Vertiform City.
Well...
I guess I was wrong
about you folks.
Welcome aboard.
What was that?
We've been having
some problems.
The engine is
running out of steam.
I hope we make it
to Vertiform City on time.
Is there anything
we can do to help?
Well, I could use
a pair of strong arms
in the engine room.
Might help us
get back on schedule.
Why don't you go
with him, Worf?
We'll see what
we can do here.
Excuse me,
are we gonna
get there okay?
Of course. You needn't
worry about a thing.
So, tell me everything
you know about Vertiform City.
Well, they got
this restaurant there
where you can eat
all you want, anytime.
It's the best
food around.
There's the coal,
and there's the boiler.
I'm much obliged
for your help.
Well done, sir.
I think this will make
a big difference, all right.
I don't know
how or why, sir,
but warp power appears to be
back at normal levels.
What's our heading?
We appear to be
on a course
for Tambor Beta VI.
It's a white dwarf star.
Keep it steady.
Put your back into it.
That's the ticket!
The ship is using
a modified tractor beam
to collect vertion
particles from the star.
Vertion particles...
Vertiform City--
that's what the ship
was looking for.
( console beeping )
The particles are
being routed through
the transporter system
into Cargo Bay Five.
Geordi,
what's going on?
The object is absorbing
vertion particles.
It's growing
even faster than before.
Commander...
I'm picking up internal energy
from this thing.
What do you mean?
I mean it's generating
its own energy.
I'm picking up
coherent emissions,
matter conversion...
it's incredible.
Wait a minute.
Something's wrong.
We've got power
fluctuations.
Vertion absorption rate
is dropping.
What's happening
with the particle beam?
The beam's exhausted
the supply of particles
in the star-- there's
nothing left to take out.
Captain, the energy output
of the object is decreasing.
Something's wrong.
What is it?
This was supposed
to be Vertiform City.
We've been on
the wrong track all along.
( screaming )
Are you all right?
Yes.
What happened?
The conductor accidentally
derailed the train.
Data to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
There's been an accident
in the holodeck, sir.
Has anything happened
on the Enterprise?
Yes, we've had
a ship-wide shutdown.
We've lost
attitude control,
and most systems
are offline.
Captain, you'd better
take a look at this.
When the particle beam
cut off, the object was
was beginning to form
a coherent energy matrix.
Now, if these readings
are accurate,
I'd say that the emission
patterns were almost organic.
Are you suggesting
that the Enterprise
is trying to create
a life-form?
I think so.
Will it survive?
Well, its energy levels
are dropping rapidly.
Unless it gets an infusion
of vertion particles--
and I mean soon--
I don't think so.
Captain, all of our systems
are back on line.
We're moving again--
at warp nine.
Let's get back
to the Bridge.
Whoo-ee.
That was a close one,
wasn't it?
Where are we going now?
Well, New Vertiform City,
of course.
Data to Captain.
Picard here.
The train has returned
to normal, sir.
Our destination is
New Vertiform City.
What's our course?
We're headed for
the Cordannas system.
Another white dwarf star.
It's the nearest one
to our last position.
LA FORGE:
Captain...
we have a problem.
Even at warp nine,
the Cordannas system
is over 12 hours
from here.
Will the object in the cargo bay
survive that long?
Yes, sir, but that's
not the problem.
The ship has diverted
all of our systems
to maximum propulsion,
including life support.
We have less than
two hours of reserve oxygen.
Mr. Data, we have
to stop the Enterprise.
That means you have to get
control of the train.
DATA:
Understood, sir.
The ship is looking
for vertion particles.
And it believes that
the Cordannas system
is the closest source--
is there any possibility
of anything closer?
White dwarf stars are
the only natural
sources of vertion, sir.
Then what about
artificial ones?
Can you create
the particles?
How did the conductor
stop the train?
There is a braking lever
in the engine room.
Let's go.
Sorry, folks,
but you ain't
going nowhere.
LA FORGE:
I've narrowed the search down
to the MacPherson nebula,
which is a supernova remnant,
and Dikon Alpha,
which is a class-9 pulsar.
They're both fairly close
to our current flight path,
and either one could
produce vertion particles
if we detonated a modified
photon torpedo inside it.
Vertions usually occur
in minuscule amounts.
Do you think either
of these phenomena
could produce
enough of them?
It's really hard to say,
I can't even guarantee
that we can
create them at all.
Well, we've got
to give it a try.
The nebula or the pulsar?
It's your choice,
Mr. La Forge.
I say go with
the nebula.
Very well.
Begin the torpedo modifications.
Now let's see if
we can get this ship
to go where we want.
Please,
listen to me.
We understand
what's happening.
We know you have to get
to New Vertiform City,
and we want to help you
get there.
Well,
I don't know.
Please.
We're your friends.
You really gonna help us
get to New Vertiform City?
I promise.
Well, okay,
but just one of you.
The rest stay here.
That's far enough.
Sorry to spoil
your party, pal.
It's nothing personal.
I can get us there
more quickly.
I know
a shorter route.
Don't listen to him.
He's up to something.
A shorter route?
Yes, if you will let me
handle the controls.
Don't do it.
Well...
we're already
behind schedule.
If you can get us
there on time...
all right, go on,
but no funny stuff.
Data to Captain Picard.
I have taken control
of the engine room.
Stand by.
Are we within sensor
range of the nebula?
Yes, Captain,
we are.
Mr. Data, I need you to
slow us to impulse speed.
I will attempt
to do so.
I hope you know
what you're doing.
Are the modifications
to the torpedoes complete?
Aye, sir.
Launch torpedo.
It's working,
Captain.
The reaction is producing
vertion particles.
Well, what do you know?
We're here!
New Vertiform City!
( laughing )
( whistle blaring )
The nodes are deactivating
all over the ship.
All our systems are beginning
to function normally again.
Then the purpose
of the ship's intelligence
was simply to bring this
life-form into being.
There are some species whose
sole purpose is to reproduce.
Once they finally
procreate, they die.
Captain...
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
The Enterprise is
back under our control.
All traces of the emergent
intelligence are gone,
and the object it created
has disappeared into space.
( door chimes )
Come.
Captain, I am staging
a scene from The Tempest
this evening for
a small audience.
I would like
for you to attend.
I would be honored.
What scene?
Miranda's first encounter
with other human beings.
"O brave new world,
that has such people in it."
It seemed appropriate.
Captain, you took
a substantial risk
in allowing
the Enterprise to...
complete its task.
Why do you say that?
Because the end result
was unknown.
The object could
have been dangerous.
It may, in fact,
be dangerous.
And I have allowed it
to go off on its merry way.
Yes, sir.
The intelligence
that was formed
on the Enterprise
didn't just come out
of the ship's systems.
It came from us,
from our mission records,
personal logs,
holodeck programs...
our fantasies.
Now, if our experiences
with the Enterprise
have been honorable,
can't we trust that
the sum of those experiences
will be the same?