Captain's Log,
Stardate 47941.7.
The Enterprise is en route
to a briefing on the situation
in the Demilitarized Zone
along the Cardassian border.
Meanwhile, we are celebrating
the return of an old friend.
LA FORGE:
Ro!
Welcome home.
Thanks. It's good
to be back.
Congratulations
on your promotion, Lieutenant.
Oh, and same to you,
Commander.
Thank you.
Say, I understand that
advanced tactical training
is a real picnic.
Right.
Did you see
the buffet?
This is real
Bajoran foraiga.
It wasn't
easy to get.
You shouldn't have gone
to all this trouble, really.
CRUSHER:
We wanted you to know how glad
we are to have you back.
TROI:
So, um...
Where are your
new quarters?
Uh, Deck Four,
Section Eight.
What are you
planning to do...?
PICARD:
Lieutenant Ro.
Go ahead, sir.
Please report to the Bridge.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
Captain.
You seemed a bit overwhelmed
by all the attention.
Well, to tell you the truth
I-I really want
to see everyone.
I would just rather
do it one at a time.
Well, you look
very fit, Lieutenant.
Tactical training
seems to agree with you.
Well, you know me.
I enjoy a challenge.
That school is more
than a challenge.
Half the class
washes out every year.
Although somehow
I didn't think you
would be one of those.
Captain...
I want you to know
that I really appreciate
your recommending me.
If it weren't for you,
my life would be
a very different
one right now.
RIKER:
Bridge to Picard.
Go ahead.
We're receiving
a distress signal
from a Cardassian ship
near the Demilitarized Zone.
Change course
to intercept.
I'm on my way.
I, um... I'd like you
at the conn, Lieutenant.
( alarm wailing )
Ensign Gates?
Report.
The Cardassian ship
relayed a distress signal
but it was cut off before we
could find out what was wrong.
I have the ship
on long-range sensors.
It appears to be under attack
by several small ships.
Can you identify them?
Uh, no, sir.
They're not transmitting
identification codes.
I will scan their
warp signatures.
Sir, sensors indicate
the attacking vessels
are Federation ships.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission--
to explore
strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
We're coming
into visual range.
On screen.
RIKER:
Those are Federation ships.
Isolate one
and magnify.
The Maquis.
Open a channel.
Open.
To all Maquis ships,
call off your attack
or we will be forced
to engage you.
No response.
You are Federation
citizens.
Your actions
are in violation
of our treaty with
the Cardassians.
Call off your attack.
DATA:
They are not responding, sir.
Mr. Worf, are we
in firing range?
Not yet, sir.
Arm phasers and
photon torpedoes
and stand by.
I never thought we'd be firing
on our own people
to protect
a Cardassian ship.
The Maquis ships
are regrouping, sir.
They are closing in
on the Cardassian vessel.
The Cardassian shields
are down to 30%.
They may not be able
to withstand another hit.
Sir, we are
within weapons range.
Mr. Worf, can you
detonate a torpedo spread
between the Maquis ships
and the Cardassians?
Yes, sir.
Do it.
The Maquis are
breaking formation.
They are withdrawing.
Signal the
Cardassians
that we're standing
by to assist them
if they have
any wounded.
Aye, sir.
Do you people
have experience
treating Cardassians?
Yes.
Do you mind?
PICARD:
Gul Evek.
I'm sorry that we could not
come to your aid sooner.
I suppose we're lucky
you came at all.
Lately, Starfleet seems
to look the other way
when the Maquis attack.
I can assure you
that is not the case.
We are doing everything
in our power to control them.
The fact that my
ship was attacked
suggests your efforts have
met with limited success.
They came at us
with photon torpedoes
and type-8 phasers.
Now, tell me, Captain.
How do you suppose that
a group of civilians
acquired such weaponry?
I can assure you that it was
not through official channels.
So, you don't think the fact
that some of the Maquis
are former
Starfleet officers
has anything
to do with it?
Starfleet does not condone
the Maquis' actions
in the Demilitarized Zone
any more than your
government would condone
the paramilitary actions
of Cardassian civilians.
We have taken measures
to deal with our colonists
who have armed themselves.
Considering that they destroyed
a Juhrayan freighter
less than a week ago,
I would say
that your efforts are meeting
with limited success.
Captain, if the Maquis
are not stopped
this situation will continue
to escalate to the point
where the Cardassian military
will have no choice
but to take matters
into their own hands.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Gul Evek and his crew
have left the Enterprise
and we have proceeded
to our rendezvous
with Admiral Nechayev.
No Bularian canapés
this time, Captain?
I thought twice
was pushing it a little.
It's just as well.
They're extremely
fattening.
You missed Gul Evek
by a matter of hours.
I asked him to stay.
I thought that an admiral's
assurances might convince him
that we are trying to deal
with this Maquis situation.
Evek manages to make
the Cardassians sound
like helpless sheep
being preyed on
by Federation wolves.
The truth is, we caught
the Cardassian government
supplying its colonies
in the Demilitarized Zone
with weapons.
Now, Gul Evek assured me that
they had stopped that practice.
( rueful chuckle )
How comforting.
Admiral, this Maquis situation
has you worried.
Believe me, Captain
if I were living that close
to the Cardassians
I'd keep a phaser
under my pillow, too
but in the last weeks,
we've seen signs
that the Maquis
are moving beyond self-defense.
Their ranks are growing.
They're acquiring ships,
weapons.
They seem
to be preparing
for a more aggressive
military posture.
We've got to put a stop to them
before the entire
Demilitarized Zone ignites.
But before
we stop them
we have to find them.
They seem to be scattered
in small cells around the Zone
and we don't have reliable
intelligence about any of them.
Perhaps you need...
an undercover operative.
Our thinking exactly.
We intend to infiltrate
their organization
and the person
we want to do it
is aboard your
ship right now.
Starfleet wants me
to infiltrate the Maquis?
Because of your recent training
because you're Bajoran
and... because of your
past troubles with Starfleet.
It gives you
a certain credibility.
Well, that's certainly true.
And just how soon
would this mission begin?
Immediately.
I see.
( sighs )
I've spent the better part
of my life
fighting the Cardassians.
I never thought
I'd be helping them out.
Well, this is a rare case
when our interests
and theirs coincide.
We both want peace
in the Demilitarized Zone.
I've heard a lot
about the Maquis.
One of my instructors
at tactical training
a Lieutenant Commander
in Starfleet--
a man I both admired
and respected--
he was sympathetic
to them.
He resigned and
left to join them.
We're all sympathetic,
Lieutenant.
Our civilian population
in the Demilitarized Zone
is in a very
difficult situation
but even sympathy
has to end at some point.
A peace treaty isn't
just a piece of paper.
If the Maquis force us
into a war with Cardassia
it could mean hundreds
of thousands of lives.
Two years ago
Starfleet would never have
tapped you for this mission.
They must have a lot
of confidence
in you now.
The way I see it
there's one good reason
to take this mission
and that's to validate
your faith in me.
( buzz of conversation )
( conversation dies down )
We are looking
for a Bajoran woman.
Dark hair.
She is responsible
for the death
of a Cardassian soldier.
( scattered laughter )
If we learn
she has been here
this establishment
will be closed down.
You say she has
dark hair?
Yes.
She was here.
You just
missed her.
Do you know
where she went?
No.
( door closes )
( conversation resumes )
Hey...
It was really nice
meeting you.
Oh...
Thanks.
So... did you kill
that Cardassian?
Starfleet thinks I did.
That's reason
enough to hide.
Why did you tell
them that I'd left?
There are worse things
a person can do
than kill
a Cardassian soldier.
You don't often
meet someone
willing to say
that out loud.
In the Zone, there are a lot
of us who feel that way.
I'd like to meet
people like that.
( gasps )
Don't be afraid.
You're not in danger here.
What is
your name?
Did you kill
that Cardassian soldier?
Who are you?
We're the people
who saved you from Starfleet.
Thanks,
but I'll be going now.
Did you kill that Cardassian?
Yes.
That's a risky thing to do
in the Demilitarized Zone.
You can end up
being hunted
by Starfleet and
the Cardassians.
Then why did he risk
bringing me here?
We're asking the questions.
Who are you?
My name is Ro Laren.
I grew up in the Bajoran camps.
Well, that would explain why you
have no love for Cardassians.
I know what they're capable of.
They tortured my father to death
and I was forced to watch.
Where are you living now?
RO:
Nowhere.
I was a Starfleet officer,
but I was court-martialed
and I was sent
to the stockade on Jaros II.
I'm not exactly what you'd call
Starfleet material.
When were you on Jaros?
What difference does it make?
We want to check your story.
When were you there?
Starfleet let me out
about three years ago
because I agreed to do
some work for them--
mostly having to do
with Bajor.
But I got tired
of watching them
placate the Cardassians,
and so I left.
You resigned?
Not officially.
That's part of the reason
why they're looking for me.
What were you doing on Ronara?
Look, I think I've answered
enough of your questions.
I would like to know
who you people are.
Let's say that we sympathize
with those who oppose Cardassia.
Are you Maquis?
What if we were?
If you were, I would ask
if I could join you
and help you fight.
We'll check your story.
Go ahead.
I'll keep an eye on her.
Come.
Let's stretch our legs.
Aren't you taking a chance
by letting me see all of this?
What if my story
doesn't check out?
What if I'm not
who I say I am?
Well, then we'll have
a problem, won't we?
You are Maquis,
aren't you?
Many of the people here are.
Starfleet considers
you outlaws.
( chuckling )
They're afraid you'll
destroy the peace treaty.
They don't understand
the situation here in the Zone.
I lived on Juhraya.
When the treaty was signed
the colony suddenly found itself
in Cardassian territory.
Some of us chose to stay,
take our chances.
Then one night, I was dragged
from my bed and beaten.
The authorities
clucked their tongues
and agreed it was
an unfortunate incident...
and did nothing.
I'm not surprised.
The Cardassians intend
to make life so unpleasant
for Federation citizens
that they'll leave.
Exactly.
And no one seems
to see that!
Except... the Maquis.
How old were you
when your father was killed?
I'd rather not
talk about that.
You hungry?
Would you like something?
No. Thank you.
Hasperat.
You like hasperat?
Uh, an old Bajoran friend
of mine used to make it
although his was stronger.
He was killed many years ago
fighting the Cardassian
occupation of Bajor.
I miss his company.
And his hasperat.
My father used to make
the strongest hasperat
you've ever tasted.
Everything else seems
mild by comparison.
Did he teach you
how to make it?
Yes, but I haven't...
I haven't tried it in years.
If you would make the brine
for a really strong hasperat--
I mean, um, eye-watering,
tongue-searing strong--
you'd make an old man
very happy.
I would enjoy
making it again.
MAN:
Macias.
I've checked with my
sources at Starfleet.
Her story's true.
I was sure it was.
Kalita, she'll stay with you
until we can
find her a room.
Ah, there you are.
We've just heard
a disturbing rumor.
Another rumor.
One that I think
we should take seriously.
A trader coming from Pendi II
said he could verify
that the Cardassians
are going to start
supplying their colonists
with biogenic weapons.
I thought every shipment
coming into the
Zone was searched.
The Cardassians always seem
to find a way around
problems like that.
Then we have to make
a preemptive strike.
Send a message
to the Cardassians
that we won't sit still
while they kill us
with toxins.
Agreed.
But we can't mount a strike
without medical supplies
and our stockpile
is dangerously low.
If we put in a request for more,
it'll draw suspicion.
I can get
medical supplies.
I served on
the Enterprise.
They always have
extra medkits on hand
for relief missions.
But you're wanted
by Starfleet.
They're not going
to give you medkits
just because
you ask for them.
I have no intention
of asking for them.
I intend to take them.
How?
The Enterprise is a fortress.
I know its security systems.
Give me a ship.
I can do this.
This is madness.
We can't let her
do something like this.
We don't know
anything about her.
I know, but she can make
very strong hasperat.
What?
We need
medical supplies.
I think...
we should let her try.
All right,
but I'm going with her.
I could use an extra hand
at the controls.
And a witness.
I've set the transporter
confinement parameters
to maximum.
We should be able
to fill our hold
with medical supplies
with just one
single beam-out.
I had no idea
it was going to be so easy.
We're approaching
the Federation border.
How do you plan to get out
of the Demilitarized Zone
without being searched
at one of the checkpoints?
We're going to cross
the border here.
There are sensor buoys
all along the border.
If we cross anywhere
other than a checkpoint
Starfleet will send a ship
to investigate.
With the right security codes
we can disable the proximity
detectors on the buoys.
Starfleet changes those codes
all the time.
I know
the encryption algorithms.
If I can access the buoys'
protocol subsystem
I should be able
to figure out the codes.
Should be able to?
Do you want this mission
to succeed?
Of course I do.
We need those medical supplies.
In that case
let me do my job.
( beeping )
I'm in.
( strident beeping )
What's wrong?
If I don't input
the right code
in the next 20 seconds
we'll trigger
the proximity alarm.
I'm getting us
out of sensor range.
Don't. If we break
the com-link
we won't be able
to try again.
( beeping )
( sighing )
It worked.
Until they change
the access codes again
we can cross
the border here.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 47943.2.
It has been over a week
since Lieutenant Ro
left the Enterprise.
We have yet to receive
any communication from her.
We picked up a request
for emergency assistance
from a Federation science ship
in the Topin system.
Are there any other
ships in the vicinity?
We're the closest.
Helm, set a course
for the Topin system.
Mr. Data, will you signal
the science ship
that we're
on our way?
It is unlikely
they would receive
our communication, sir.
The Topin system contains
an unstable protostar.
It generates significant
magnetascopic interference.
Can we use our
sensors to find them?
Most of our sensors
would be ineffective
although our directional array
should cut through
the interference.
That array has
such a narrow scan field.
We might as well break out
the palm beacons
and try to find them
that way.
This is insane.
We're sitting here--
no sensors,
blind to the outside--
waiting for
a Galaxy-class starship
to come swooping down on us.
Don't worry.
It'll be hard
for them to locate us
with just their
directional sensors.
Besides, they're looking
for a damaged science ship
that wants to be found.
( beeping )
They're here.
Stand by to
engage thrusters.
RIKER:
Anything?
No, sir, it will take
approximately six hours
to scan the system.
Captain, the distress call
is being repeated.
Data, can you
locate the signal?
I am attempting to do so.
They're scanning
our last position.
All right, I've locked
onto their sensor beam.
I'm going to use it
to maneuver into
transporter range.
How are we going to beam
through their shields?
We can't.
If we're going to get
those medical supplies
we're going to have
to take this ship
through their shields.
Sir, I am scanning the area
from which the distress signal
was sent, but I'm unable
to detect a vessel.
Captain, the computer
has detected
a piggyback communication
on the last distress signal.
Can you decode it?
It will take a few moments.
Do it.
The Enterprise shields
have a weak point.
When the ship is at impulse,
the thrust destabilizes
the shield configuration
right at this point.
I'm going to try to
punch through there.
Won't they detect us?
They'll know something's
penetrated the shields
but, with all
the interference
it'll take them a
few seconds to find us.
We'll have to beam
the medical supplies aboard
and get out fast.
The message is difficult
to decode.
Interference has garbled
much of the transmission
but it seems to be coming
from Lieutenant Ro.
Ro is on that ship.
DATA:
Sir
a vessel of some kind
is attempting to penetrate
our aft shields.
Let it through.
We're going to make it.
All right, we're in.
Energizing.
Let's get out of here.
Captain, a quantity
of medical supplies
was beamed from Cargo Bay Seven.
The vessel that penetrated our
shields is of the same design
as the ships used by the Maquis.
It is moving off.
Let it go.
There must be
someone with her.
We should make it
look as though
we're trying to stop them.
Mr. Worf, lock phasers
on their previous position
and fire.
Aye, sir.
Now we know what they mean
by advanced tactical training.
You took your ship
through their shields?
Ro parked us between
their warp nacelles.
I thought she was crazy,
but it worked.
She knew exactly
what she was doing.
Well done.
We'll have to
inventory supplies
and find out what we have.
See you later.
Well, it seems
Kalita has decided
that you're not
a Federation spy after all.
( chuckles )
She's suspicious
of everyone at first
and rightly so.
We've learned to be cautious
of strangers.
No, I understand.
But I've known
since I first met you
that, in your heart,
you're one of us.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Having earned
the Maquis' trust
with her raid on the Enterprise
Lieutenant Ro has been given
access to a ship
and allowed to leave
the settlement by herself.
There are rumors
that the Cardassians
are supplying their colonists
with biogenic weapons.
Frankly, I find that hard
to believe.
Every ship that enters
the Demilitarized Zone
is being searched.
Well, the Maquis are convinced
that the Cardassians
are finding a way around
these searches.
You know, we could
make use of that.
Sir?
We have come up with a plan
that has the potential
to seriously curtail
the Maquis.
We want to give them a target
so threatening to them
that they'll be willing
to commit as many ships
and people as possible
in order to destroy it.
What do you mean,
"give them a target"?
Well, biogenic weapons,
for example.
You could provide them
with intelligence
which would show
that the Cardassians
are in fact supplying
their colonists with them.
That would get
their attention, all right.
You could tell them
that in order to get
past the checkpoints
they're shipping
the components
for these weapons
through third parties
and then, we could
put together a convoy
and send it towards
the Demilitarized Zone.
And when the Maquis
attack it
Starfleet would be
waiting for them.
We could station our ships
in the Hugora Nebula
to avoid detection.
Basically, I would
be leading them into a trap.
That's right.
If you have a problem
with any of this
I need to know it now.
Well, if I do, sir
it will not stop me
from carrying out my duty.
I knew that I
could count on you.
It took me a while,
but I managed
to patch through
into Starfleet's comsystem.
I intercepted
communication
from one of the checkpoints
along the border.
They're concerned
because a Pakled transport
came through carrying
retroviral vaccines.
Why is that
a concern?
Well, last week,
a Ferengi transport came through
carrying biomimetic gels.
By themselves,
neither of these is dangerous
but Starfleet
is concerned
because, along
with other components
the Cardassians could
put together a biogenic device.
Well, what is Starfleet
going to do about it?
They can't do anything about it.
These items
are all perfectly legal.
How close are the Cardassians
to having
the components they need?
Very close.
Two days ago, a Yridian convoy
left Deep Space 9
for the Demilitarized Zone.
It's carrying isomiotic hypos
plasma flares
and quarantine pods.
We can't let that convoy
reach its destination.
But it's too big for us
to go after alone.
I'll discuss the situation
with the other cell leaders.
Considering what's at stake
they'll want
to help.
I've sent a communication
to the others.
When this is over,
we'll celebrate.
When it's over?
When Cardassia realizes
they can't intimidate us
into leaving
our colonies.
Something tells me
it'll be a long time
before we're celebrating.
Don't be discouraged, Ro.
It'll take time
but the important thing
is that we not give up.
I spent ten years in the camps.
I don't give up.
I've been thinking
a long time
about what our
celebration will be like.
We'll have a huge dinner.
You'll make hasperat and
I'll make blueberry pie.
We'll drink wine
and we'll dance.
I'll even play
the belaklavion.
That'll give everyone
a laugh.
You play
the klavion?
Yes. Badly.
It's a difficult instrument
but I enjoy the challenge.
My father played
the klavion.
When I was very young
and afraid of monsters
under my bed...
he'd play for me.
He said that the klavion
had special powers.
Monsters were afraid of it
and when
they heard it
they would disappear.
When I listened to that music
he played for me...
I was never afraid
to go to sleep.
When he died...
I realized even he couldn't
make all the monsters go away.
Why wait?
Let's go to the market.
Let's get food
for a feast.
For a celebration.
A celebration of what?
Of absolutely nothing.
Just to celebrate.
I'd like that.
Come, let's go
to the market.
If I'm to make a pie
we'll have to find a
substitute for blueberries.
I haven't seen
real ones in years.
On Bajor, there's
a berry called teakle.
Yes, I know--
very sweet.
( people yelling and screaming )
Ro!
( grunts )
( yells )
Macias!
( groans )
( breathing heavily )
They must have discovered that
there was a Maquis cell here.
Kalita, get one of the medkits.
Hurry!
( breathing heavily )
You have to hang on.
When an old fighter
like me dies...
someone always steps forward
to take his place.
Mmm...
Not tonight.
Hello.
Are you alone?
I hope not.
Why don't we
get acquainted?
There's a table in the back
that's more private.
I'd like that.
We have to cancel
the mission.
Why?
Well, the Maquis didn't
go for the bait.
They think the convoy
is... too big a target.
There are only
six ships.
We could even
cut back that number.
It's the commitment
of resources
of grouping so many
of the Maquis
together at once.
They feel that it makes
them too vulnerable.
Every intelligence report
that I get from Starfleet
suggests that the Maquis
are eager
to expand their strikes.
They want to escalate
their activities.
Now you're telling me
this isn't true?
It's probably
different in every cell.
The people I've
met tend to be...
more conservative.
I'm sure others have
a more militant attitude.
Laren, what's going on?
Do you have the money
I asked you to bring?
Yes.
Put some
on the table.
What?
By this time, you should
be negotiating my price.
When you sent me
on this mission...
I thought that
I could do it.
Even though it meant
helping the Cardassians.
betraying people
who were fighting
against them.
Now I'm not sure
where I stand.
Are you saying that you want
to back out of this mission?
Sir, I don't want
to let you down.
I swear that I don't.
This has nothing
to do with me.
This is about you.
If you back out now
you'll throw away
everything you've worked for.
We're committed
to this mission.
My only question
for you is:
Can you carry out
your orders?
I could put you before
a Board of Inquiry
for having lied to me
about this operation.
I would certainly
have you court-martialed
if you sabotage it.
Now, it's your decision.
I'll carry out
my orders, sir.
I feel it necessary
to have...
have Commander Riker
go back with you.
He can... pose as...
a relative.
I just want
to make sure that...
nothing happens
to obstruct this mission.
Sorry. I don't have
that kind of money.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have received word
from Commander Riker
and Lieutenant Ro
that the Maquis
will be attacking the convoy
as planned.
Our ships
have taken up position
in the Hugora Nebula
to wait for them.
I have established
a relay link
with the sensor probe
we left on the perimeter
of the nebula.
This is the convoy.
We are expecting
the Maquis attack force
to cross the border
from the Demilitarized Zone.
As soon as they cross the
border, we'll intercept them.
Captain, in order to ensure
that the ship Commander Riker
and Lieutenant Ro are piloting
does not come under fire
I have relayed
their warp signature
to the rest
of the attack force.
Sir, the Maquis squadron
is coming into
sensor range.
Go to red alert.
Aye, sir.
MAN:
Squad leader to all ships.
Go ahead,
squad leader.
We'll be crossing the border
in less than one minute.
Arm your weapons.
RO:
Acknowledged.
Starfleet can't make its move
until we're out
of the Demilitarized Zone.
We're to break formation
and take cover in the nebula
as soon as they appear.
The ships in the convoy
are raising their shields.
They've spotted us.
We cross the border
in 30 seconds.
What the...?
I'm sorry.
I can't let this happen.
Sir, the vessel being piloted
by Lieutenant Ro
is firing a low-intensity
particle beam into the nebula.
What the hell
is she doing?
The polarizing effect
being created by the beam
may make it possible
for us to be detected.
Can you counter
the effect?
I will attempt to do so.
Ro, why are you firing?
Scan the nebula.
There's a Starfleet attack
force hiding inside it.
I see it.
Squad leader to all ships.
Abort the mission.
Repeat-- abort the mission.
Sir, the Maquis ships
are breaking formation.
PICARD:
Have they crossed
the border?
DATA:
No, sir.
They are withdrawing.
WORF:
Captain.
( console beeping )
Lieutenant Ro's ship
is not retreating
with the others.
It is heading towards us.
When she comes aboard...
take her into custody.
Alpha Seven to Alpha Nine.
KALITA:
Go ahead.
Stand by to beam me aboard.
Standing by.
You can take this ship
back to the Enterprise.
You're going with them?
It's been a long time
since I really felt
like I belonged somewhere.
Could you tell Captain Picard
something for me?
Of course.
What is it?
Tell him I'm sorry.
So long, Ro.
Take care of yourself.
Good-bye, Will.
Energize.
She seemed very sure
that she was doing
the right thing.
I think her only regret
was that she let you down.
Here's my report.