THAT WAS
AN INCREDIBLE PROGRAM.
I AM GLAD YOU APPROVE.
I HAVE ALWAYS FOUND
THE BLACK SEA AT NIGHT
TO BE A MOST
STIMULATING EXPERIENCE.
WORF, WE WERE WALKING
BAREFOOT ON THE BEACH
WITH BALALAIKA MUSIC
IN THE AIR
OCEAN BREEZE WASHING OVER US
STARS IN THE SKY,
A FULL MOON RISING
AND THE MOST YOU CAN SAY
IS "STIMULATING"?
IT WAS...
VERY STIMULATING.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, I DON'T SPEND NEARLY
ENOUGH TIME ON THE HOLODECK.
I SHOULD TAKE MY OWN ADVICE
AND GO THERE TO RELAX.
NEXT TIME I'LL
CHOOSE THE PROGRAM.
IF YOU LIKED THE BLACK SEA
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE
LAKE CATARIA ON BETAZED.
DEANNA, PERHAPS BEFORE
THERE IS A NEXT TIME
WE SHOULD DISCUSS
COMMANDER RIKER.
WHY? IS HE COMING ALONG?
NO.
BUT I DO NOT WISH...
IT WOULD BE UNFORTUNATE
IF HE...
IF YOU AND I
ARE GOING TO CONTINUE
I DO NOT WISH
TO HURT HIS FEELINGS.
WORF, I THINK IT'S ALL RIGHT
TO CONCENTRATE ON OUR FEELINGS--
YOURS AND MINE.
Picard:
COUNSELOR...
WHAT'S TODAY'S DATE?
THE DATE.
Worf:
STARDATE 47988.
47988.
CAPTAIN, WHAT'S WRONG?
I'M NOT SURE.
I DON'T KNOW... HOW OR WHY
BUT... I'M MOVING
BACK AND FORTH THROUGH TIME.
( dramatic theme playing )
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS CONTINUING MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO ONE HAS GONE BEFORE.
( adventurous theme playing )
I HAD THIS FEELING THAT I'D
PHYSICALLY LEFT THE ENTERPRISE.
I WAS IN ANOTHER TIME,
ANOTHER PLACE.
I WAS SOMEWHERE IN THE PAST.
CAN YOU DESCRIBE
WHERE YOU WERE
WHAT IT LOOKED LIKE?
YOU SEE, IT'S ALL
SLIPPING AWAY SO FAST.
IT'S LIKE... IT'S LIKE
WAKING UP FROM A NIGHTMARE.
I, UH...
IT WAS YEARS AGO.
I-I-IT WAS BEFORE
I TOOK COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
I WAS TALKING
TO SOMEONE.
I CAN'T REMEMBER WHO.
AND THEN IT ALL CHANGED.
I WAS NO LONGER IN THE PAST.
I WAS NOW AN OLD MAN
IN THE FUTURE
AND... I WAS OUTSIDE,
AND I WAS DOING SOMETHING.
( whispering ):
I CAN'T REMEMBER WHAT IT WAS.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S, IT'S ALL GONE.
I JUST CAN'T REMEMBER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HAVE YOU CONSIDERED
THE POSSIBILITY
THAT THIS WAS JUST A DREAM?
NO, NO.
IT WAS MUCH MORE THAN A DREAM.
THE SMELLS, THE SOUNDS...
THE, THE VERY TOUCH OF THINGS--
MUCH MORE REAL THAN A DREAM.
HOW LONG DID YOU SPEND
IN EACH TIME PERIOD?
DID IT SEEM LIKE MINUTES?
HOURS?
I CAN'T SAY.
AT FIRST, I HAD A SENSE OF...
A SENSE OF CONFUSION,
DISORIENTATION.
I WASN'T SURE WHERE I WAS
AND THEN ALL
OF THAT PASSED
AND IT ALL SEEMED
PERFECTLY NATURAL
AS THOUGH I BELONGED
IN THAT TIME
BUT... I CAN'T...
( dramatic theme playing )
CAPTAIN PICARD
TO THE BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM
WITH THE WARP CORE
OR THE PHASE INDUCERS
OR SOME OTHER DAMN THING.
GEORDI.
HELLO, CAPTAIN.
OR SHOULD I
CALL YOU AMBASSADOR?
OH, I HAVEN'T
BEEN CALLED THAT
FOR SOME TIME, EITHER.
HOW ABOUT "MR. PICARD"?
HOW ABOUT "JEAN-LUC"?
I DON'T THINK I COULD
GET USED TO THAT.
GOOD LORD, GEORDI.
WELL... HOW LONG
HAS IT BEEN?
NINE YEARS.
NO, NO, NO, SINCE YOU
LAST CALLED ME CAPTAIN--
SINCE WE WERE ALL TOGETHER
ON THE ENTERPRISE.
CLOSE TO 25 YEARS.
25 YEARS.
WELL, TIME HAS BEEN
GOOD TO YOU.
A LITTLE TOO GOOD
IN SOME PLACES.
CAN I GIVE YOU A HAND HERE?
OH, WELL, I'M, UH...
I'M JUST TYING UP
SOME VINES.
MMM, YOU GOT LEAF MINERS.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TRY
A BACILLUS SPRAY.
MY WIFE IS QUITE A GARDENER.
I'VE PICKED UP
A LITTLE BIT OF IT.
HOW IS LEAH?
JUST WONDERFUL,
BUSY AS EVER.
SHE'S JUST BEEN
MADE DIRECTOR
OF THE DAYSTROM INSTITUTE.
WHAT ABOUT THE LITTLE ONES--
BRET, ALANDRA, AND, UM...
SIDNEY.
WELL, THEY'RE NOT
SO LITTLE ANYMORE.
BRET IS APPLYING
TO STARFLEET ACADEMY
NEXT YEAR.
SO WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE?
OH, I JUST THOUGHT I'D STOP BY.
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT
THE OLD DAYS ON THE ENTERPRISE.
I WAS IN
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
GEORDI, YOU DON'T MAKE THE TRIP
FROM RIGEL THREE TO EARTH
JUST TO DROP BY.
NO.
SO... YOU HEARD.
LEAH'S GOT A FEW FRIENDS
AT STARFLEET MEDICAL.
WORD GETS AROUND.
I'M NOT AN INVALID.
IRUMODIC SYNDROME CAN TAKE YEARS
TO RUN ITS COURSE.
I KNOW.
ONCE I HEARD
WELL, I JUST WANTED
TO STOP BY JUST THE SAME.
WELL, NOW THAT YOU'RE HERE
YOU CAN HELP ME
CARRY THOSE TOOLS.
WELL, MY COOKING MAY NOT BE
UP TO LEAH'S STANDARDS
BUT I CAN STILL MAKE
A DECENT CUP OF TEA.
OH, I READ YOUR LAST NOVEL.
I THOUGHT
THAT THE PROTAGONIST
WAS A LITTLE TOO FLAMBOYANT
BUT, FOR THE REST, I...
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
CAPTAIN!
Woman:
CAPTAIN,
WILL THIS BE YOUR FIRST TIME
ON A GALAXY-CLASS SHIP?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, SIR?
SIR?
I'M... I'M SORRY,
LIEUTENANT.
MY MIND MUST HAVE WANDERED.
WHAT WERE YOU SAYING?
I WAS ASKING
IF YOU'D EVER BEEN
ABOARD A GALAXY-CLASS
STARSHIP BEFORE.
NO.
OF COURSE, I'M FAMILIAR
WITH THE BLUEPRINTS
AND THE SPECIFICATIONS
BUT THIS WILL BE
MY FIRST TIME ONBOARD.
WELL, THEN,
IF I MAY BE SO BOLD, SIR
YOU'RE IN FOR A TREAT.
THE ENTERPRISE IS QUITE A SHIP.
I'M SURE SHE IS.
HAVE I DONE
SOMETHING WRONG, SIR?
NO.
IT'S JUST THAT YOU LOOK
VERY FAMILIAR.
Man:
Enterprise to
Shuttlecraft Galileo.
You are cleared for arrival
in Shuttlebay Two.
ACKNOWLEDGED, ENTERPRISE.
AND THERE SHE IS.
( majestic theme playing )
Troi:
CAPTAIN.
TASHA.
I WAS JUST WITH TASHA
IN THE SHUTTLE.
I JUST FINISHED
THE NEUROGRAPHIC SCAN.
I DIDN'T FIND ANYTHING
THAT WOULD CAUSE HALLUCINATIONS
OR A PSYCHOGENIC REACTION.
IS THERE ANY INDICATION
OF TEMPORAL DISPLACEMENT?
NO. USUALLY A TEMPORAL SHIFT
WOULD LEAVE SOME SORT OF
TRYPTAMINE RESIDUE
IN THE CEREBRAL CORTEX, BUT THE
SCAN DIDN'T SHOW ANY.
PERSONALLY, I THINK YOU JUST
ENJOY WAKING EVERYBODY UP
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT.
ACTUALLY, I REALLY LIKE RUNNING
AROUND THE SHIP IN MY BARE FEET.
THE BIOSPECTRAL
TEST RESULTS, DOCTOR.
YOUR BLOOD GAS ANALYSIS
IS CONSISTENT WITH SOMEONE
WHO'S BEEN BREATHING
THE SHIP'S AIR FOR WEEKS.
IF YOU'D BEEN
ANYWHERE ELSE
THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN
AN INDICATION OF CHANGE
IN THE OXYGEN
ISOTOPE RATIOS.
THANKS.
DEANNA, WOULD YOU
EXCUSE US, PLEASE?
OF COURSE.
JEAN-LUC, I SCANNED YOU
FOR EVIDENCE
OF IRUMODIC SYNDROME
AS YOU SUGGESTED.
THERE WASN'T ANY.
BUT I DID FIND
A SMALL STRUCTURAL DEFECT
IN THE PARIETAL LOBE.
A DEFECT THAT YOU
HADN'T NOTICED BEFORE?
IT'S THE KIND OF DEFECT
THAT WOULD ONLY SHOW UP
ON A LEVEL-FOUR
NEUROGRAPHIC SCAN
THAT COULD CAUSE YOU
TO BE SUSCEPTIBLE
TO SEVERAL KINDS OF NEUROLOGICAL
DISORDERS
INCLUDING
IRUMODIC SYNDROME.
NOW IT'S POSSIBLE FOR YOU
TO LIVE WITH THIS DEFECT
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE
WITHOUT DEVELOPING A PROBLEM
OR EVEN IF YOU DO,
MANY PEOPLE CONTINUE
TO LIVE NORMAL LIVES
FOR A LONG TIME
AFTER THE ONSET
OF IRUMODIC SYNDROME.
IF THAT'S SO, WHY DO YOU LOOK
AS IF YOU'VE JUST SIGNED
MY DEATH SENTENCE?
I'M SORRY.
I GUESS...
IT CAUGHT ME OFF GUARD.
I WOULDN'T WORRY
ABOUT IT.
SOMETHING TELLS ME
THAT YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO PUT UP WITH ME
FOR A LONG TIME TO COME.
WELL, IT WON'T BE EASY,
BUT I'LL MANAGE.
( door slides open )
Riker: CAPTAIN.
HAS WORF FOUND ANYTHING?
NO, SIR. HIS SECURITY SCANS
CAME UP NEGATIVE.
THEY'RE STILL CHECKING
THE SENSOR LOGS
BUT THERE IS
NO INDICATION
THAT YOU EVER
LEFT THE SHIP.
I WASN'T DREAMING.
SOMETHING HAPPENED.
Worf to Captain.
GO AHEAD, MR. WORF.
Sir, there is
an incoming transmission
from Admiral Nakamura.
It is a priority one message.
BEVERLY?
MR. WORF,
WILL YOU ROUTE THE CALL
THROUGH TO DR. CRUSHER'S OFFICE?
Aye, sir.
Nakamura:
Captain.
ADMIRAL.
I am initiating
a fleet-wide yellow alert.
Starfleet intelligence
has picked up
some alarming reports
from the Romulan Empire.
It appears that at least
30 Warbirds have been pulled
from other assignments
and are headed
for the Neutral Zone.
IS THERE ANY EXPLANATION
WHY THEY WOULD MAKE
SUCH A BLATANTLY
AGGRESSIVE MOVE?
Our operatives on Romulus
have indicated
that there appears
to be something happening
in the Neutral Zone
specifically
in the Devron System.
Our own long-range scans
picked up some spatial anomaly
in the area.
We can't tell what it is.
WHAT ARE OUR ORDERS?
This is a very
delicate situation.
I'm deploying 15 starships
along our side
of the Neutral Zone.
I want you to go there as well.
See if you can find out
what is going on
in the Devron System.
AM I AUTHORIZED
TO ENTER THE NEUTRAL ZONE?
Not yet.
Wait and see
what the Romulans do.
You can conduct
long-range scans,
send probes if necessary,
but do not cross the border
unless they do.
UNDERSTOOD.
Starfleet out.
( computer beeps )
CAPTAIN...
WHAT'S WRONG?
THIS IS NOT MY TIME.
I DON'T BELONG HERE.
WHAT?
I WAS SOMEWHERE ELSE
A FEW MOMENTS AGO.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU'VE BEEN RIGHT HERE
WITH ME.
NO! NO! NO!
I WAS SOMEWHERE ELSE.
I WAS... IT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
THERE WAS SOMEONE TALKING.
I WAS... I-I...
I WAS TALKING TO SOMEONE.
BEVERLY.
I WAS TALKING TO BEVERLY.
IT'S OKAY, CAPTAIN.
EVERYTHING'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M NOT SENILE, YOU KNOW.
THIS DID HAPPEN.
I-I-I WAS HERE
I WAS TALKING TO YOU,
AND THEN...
AND THEN I WAS
SOMEWHERE ELSE
I WAS, UH...
I WAS ON THE ENTERPRISE.
I WAS BACK ON THE ENTERPRISE.
AT LEAST I... I THINK
THAT'S WHERE IT WAS.
I WAS IN SICK BAY.
WELL, IT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN A HOSPITAL.
CAPTAIN, I THINK WE
SHOULD GO BACK TO THE HOUSE
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR.
YES, YES, I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
IT'S THE IRUMODIC SYNDROME.
HE'S BEGINNING TO LOSE HIS MIND,
THE OLD MAN.
WELL, IT'S NOT THAT,
AND I'M NOT DAYDREAMING EITHER.
WELL, ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
SO, WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DO ABOUT IT?
DATA.
I WANT TO SEE DATA.
DATA-- WHY?
'CAUSE I THINK
HE CAN HELP.
HELP HOW?
I DON'T KNOW!
I WANT TO SEE DATA.
OKAY, THEN.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO SEE DATA.
HE'S STILL AT CAMBRIDGE,
ISN'T HE?
YES, I-I THINK HE IS.
( shouting indistinctly )
YOU SEE THEM, DON'T YOU?
SEE WHO?
THEY'RE EVERYWHERE.
THEY'RE LAUGHING AT ME.
WHY ARE THEY LAUGHING?
COME ON, CAPTAIN.
LET'S GO SEE DATA.
YES.
DATA.
WE'LL GO SEE DATA.
I KNOW HOW IT SOUNDS,
BUT IT HAPPENED.
IT WAS REAL.
I WAS THERE, BACK ONBOARD
THE ENTERPRISE.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
YOUR TEA?
TEA? EARL GREY. HOT.
OF COURSE IT'S HOT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT IN IT?
NOTHING.
WELL, DATA,
I MUST SAY
THIS IS A FINE PLACE
YOU HAVE HERE.
THEY CERTAINLY TREAT
PROFESSORS VERY WELL
AT CAMBRIDGE.
HOLDING A LUCASIAN CHAIR
DOES HAVE ITS PERQUISITES.
THIS HOUSE ORIGINALLY BELONGED
TO SIR ISAAC NEWTON
WHEN HE HELD THE POSITION.
IT'S BECOME
THE TRADITIONAL RESIDENCE.
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
IF YOU'RE REALLY
HIS FRIEND
YOU'LL GET HIM
TO TAKE THAT GRAY
OUT OF HIS HAIR.
JESSEL...
LOOKS LIKE
A BLOODY SKUNK.
SHE CAN BE FRIGHTFULLY TRYING
AT TIMES
BUT SHE DOES
MAKE ME LAUGH.
DATA, WHAT IS IT
WITH THE HAIR ANYWAY?
I FOUND THAT A TOUCH OF GRAY
ADDS AN AIR OF... DISTINCTION.
YOU SAID THIS IS EARL GREY?
I'D SWEAR THAT
IT WAS DARJEELING.
CAPTAIN, HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
SINCE YOU'VE SEEN A DOCTOR
ABOUT YOUR
IRUMODIC SYNDROME?
A WEEK.
THEY PRESCRIBED PERIDAXON.
Data:
BUT, SIR, PERIDAXON...
YES I KNOW-- IT'S NOT A CURE.
THERE'S NOTHING THAT CAN PREVENT
THE DETERIORATION
OF THE SYNAPTIC PATHWAYS.
YOU THINK THAT I'M SENILE
THAT ALL THIS
IS JUST A DELUSION.
NOW, COME ON, CAPTAIN, NO ONE
SAID ANYTHING OF THE KIND.
IN ALL HONESTY, CAPTAIN
THE THOUGHT
HAS OCCURRED TO ME.
HOWEVER
THERE'S NOTHING
TO DISPROVE WHAT YOUR SAYING.
SO IT'S POSSIBLE
SOMETHING IS HAPPENING TO YOU.
THE FIRST THING WE SHOULD DO
IS RUN A COMPLETE SERIES
OF NEUROGRAPHIC SCANS.
WE CAN USE THE EQUIPMENT
IN THE BIOMETRIC LAB
HERE ON THE CAMPUS.
JESSEL, ASK PROFESSOR RIPPERT
TO TAKE OVER MY LECTURE
FOR TOMORROW, POSSIBLY
FOR THE REST OF THE WEEK.
CAPTAIN, WE'LL GET
TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS.
THAT'S THE DATA
THAT I REMEMBER.
I KNEW THAT I COULD
COUNT ON YOU.
COMMANDING OFFICER,
ENTERPRISE ARRIVING.
( shrill tone )
"TO CAPTAIN JEAN-LUC PICARD,
STARDATE 41148...
( angry shouting )
"...YOU ARE HEREBY REQUESTED
AND REQUIRED TO TAKE COMMAND...
( indistinct shouting )
"...TO TAKE... COMMAND
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
"AS OF THIS DATE.
SIGNED REAR ADMIRAL NORAL SATIE,
STARFLEET COMMAND."
( all shouting angrily )
RED ALERT!
ALL CREW TO BATTLE STATIONS!
Tasha:
YOU HEARD HIM.
MOVE!
( alarm blaring )
Picard:
PERSONAL LOG, STARDATE 41153.7.
RECORDED UNDER SECURITY LOCKOUT
OMEGA 327.
I HAVE DECIDED NOT TO INFORM
THIS CREW OF MY EXPERIENCES.
IF IT'S TRUE
THAT I'VE TRAVELED TO THE PAST,
I CANNOT RISK GIVING THEM
FOREKNOWLEDGE
OF WHAT'S TO COME.
REPORT.
WE'VE COMPLETED
A FULL SUBSPACE SCAN
OF THE SHIP
AND SURROUNDING SPACE.
WE'VE DETECTED NO UNUSUAL
READINGS OR ANOMALIES.
Worf:
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
IT WOULD BE HELPFUL
IF WE KNEW
EXACTLY WHAT
WE WERE LOOKING FOR.
NOTED.
COUNSELOR, DO YOU SENSE
ANYTHING UNUSUAL
ONBOARD THE ENTERPRISE?
PERHAPS AN ALIEN PRESENCE
THAT DOESN'T BELONG HERE--
MAYBE ONE OPERATING
ON A LEVEL OF INTELLIGENCE
FAR SUPERIOR TO OUR OWN?
NO, SIR. I'M ONLY AWARE
OF THE CREW
AND THE FAMILIES
ONBOARD THE SHIP.
MR. WORF, INITIATE A LEVEL TWO
SECURITY ALERT,
ALL DECKS,
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, SIR,
I'M THE SECURITY CHIEF
ON THIS SHIP.
UNLESS... YOU'RE PLANNING
TO MAKE A CHANGE.
NO, UH... OF COURSE NOT.
LIEUTENANT, SECURITY ALERT TWO.
AYE, SIR.
O'Brien:
Captain Picard to the bridge.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY, CHIEF.
SIR, STARFLEET
JUST ISSUED AN ALERT.
IT APPEARS A NUMBER OF VESSELS
ARE MOVING TOWARD
THE NEUTRAL ZONE
BETWEEN ROMULAN
AND FEDERATION SPACE.
WHAT KIND OF VESSELS?
FREIGHTERS, TRANSPORT.
ALL CIVILIANS,
NONE OF THEM
STARFLEET SHIPS.
THIS TELLS ME
THAT A LARGE SPATIAL ANOMALY
HAS APPEARED
IN THE NEUTRAL ZONE
IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
CAPTAIN, IT COULD BE
A ROMULAN TRICK
TO LURE OUR SHIPS
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
AS AN EXCUSE
FOR A MILITARY STRIKE.
STARFLEET'S CANCELING
OUR MISSION TO FARPOINT STATION
AND ORDERING US
TO THE NEUTRAL ZONE,
AS SOON AS WE LEAVE
THE SPACE DOCK.
NO, WE'LL PROCEED TO FARPOINT.
SIR?
YOU HEARD ME.
CAPTAIN, THE SECURITY
OF THE FEDERATION
COULD BE AT STAKE.
MR. WORF, WILL YOU
MAN YOUR STATION.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, PERHAPS IF WE
UNDERSTOOD YOUR THINKING,
IF YOU COULD EXPLAIN...
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF EXPLAINING TO ANYONE.
WE WILL PROCEED WITH OUR MISSION
TO FARPOINT AS PLANNED.
CHIEF O'BRIEN,
AM I RIGHT IN THINKING
THAT ARE YOU HAVING A PROBLEM
WITH THE WARP PLASMA INDUCERS?
THAT'S RIGHT, SIR.
WELL, I KNOW HOW TO GET THEM
BACK ONLINE. YOU'RE WITH ME.
WE'LL BE IN
MAIN ENGINEERING.
MR. O'BRIEN, WILL YOU USE
THESE SPECIFICATIONS
TO BYPASS THE SECONDARY
PLASMA INDUCER?
YOU HAVE TO REALIZE, SIR
THIS ISN'T EXACTLY
MY AREA OF EXPERTISE.
THE CHIEF ENGINEER
SHOULD BE MAKING
THESE MODIFICATIONS.
BUT THE CHIEF ENGINEER
ISN'T ONBOARD.
MR. O'BRIEN, TRUST ME.
I KNOW YOU CAN DO IT.
ALL THOSE YEARS
YOU SPENT AS A CHILD
BUILDING THOSE MODEL
STARSHIP ENGINES
THEY WERE WELL WORTH IT.
HOW DID YOU
KNOW THAT, SIR?
FROM YOUR STARFLEET RECORDS.
YES, SIR.
I'LL GET RIGHT
TO THESE MODIFICATIONS.
FLETCHER, TELL MUNOZ AND LEE
TO GET UP HERE RIGHT AWAY.
AYE, SIR.
WE HAVE TO REALIGN THE ENTIRE
POWER GRID.
WE'LL ALL BE BURNING
THE MIDNIGHT OIL ON THIS ONE.
THAT WOULD BE INADVISABLE.
EXCUSE ME?
IF YOU ATTEMPT TO IGNITE
A PETROLEUM PRODUCT
ON THIS SHIP AT 00:00 HOURS,
YOU WILL ACTIVATE
THE FIRE
SUPPRESSION SYSTEM
WHICH WOULD SEAL OFF
THIS ENTIRE COMPARTMENT.
O'Brien:
THAT WAS JUST AN EXPRESSION.
Data:
EXPRESSION OF WHAT?
O'Brien:
A FIGURE OF SPEECH.
I WAS TRYING TO TELL HIM
THAT WE'D BE WORKING LATE.
AH. THEN "TO BURN THE MIDNIGHT
OIL" IMPLIES LATE WORK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HMM. I AM CURIOUS.
WHAT IS THE ETYMOLOGY
OF THAT IDIOM?
HOW DID IT
COME TO BE USED
IN CONTEMPORARY
LANGUAGE?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
COMMANDER DATA,
WELCOME ONBOARD.
IT'S SO VERY GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
IT IS GOOD TO SEE
YOU, TOO, SIR.
I COULD USE YOUR HELP
WITH THE INFUSER ARRAY.
CERTAINLY.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
WE'RE HAVING PROBLEMS
WITH THE PLASMA CONDUITS.
THIS WILL NEED
A COMPLETELY NEW
FIELD INDUCTION SUBPROCESSOR.
IT APPEARS WE WILL BE REQUIRED
TO IGNITE
THE MIDNIGHT PETROLEUM, SIR.
Beverly:
JEAN-LUC, WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT HAPPENED AGAIN.
THE TIME SHIFT?
YEAH.
WHAT HAPPENED?
IT'S STILL A LITTLE VAGUE
BUT I CAN REMEMBER MORE
THIS TIME.
IT SEEMS THAT EVERY TIME
I SHIFT PERIODS
I CAN RETAIN MORE MEMORY.
AT FIRST, IT APPEARED
THAT I WAS IN THE FUTURE--
YEARS FROM NOW--
AND THEN,
I WAS IN THE PAST
JUST BEFORE
OUR FIRST MISSION.
WHAT IS IT?
I JUST SCANNED HIS TEMPORAL LOBE
AND COMPARED IT
WITH THE SCAN I PERFORMED
JUST A FEW MINUTES BEFORE.
THERE'S A 13 PERCENT INCREASE
IN THE ACETYLCHOLINE
OF THE HIPPOCAMPUS.
WITHIN A MATTER
OF MINUTES
YOU HAVE ACCUMULATED
OVER TWO DAYS' WORTH
OF MEMORIES.
COUNSELOR,
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHEN I FIRST CAME
ONBOARD THE ENTERPRISE?
YES.
WHAT HAPPENED
AFTER THE WELCOMING CEREMONY?
THERE WAS A RECEPTION
IN TEN FORWARD.
I INTRODUCED YOU TO WORF
AND THE OTHER SENIOR OFFICERS.
DO YOU HAVE ANY MEMORY
OF MY CALLING RED ALERT
IN THE SPACE DOCK?
DO YOU REMEMBER STARFLEET
DIVERTING US
FROM FARPOINT
TO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
TO INVESTIGATE
A SPATIAL ANOMALY?
NO.
Data:
IT WOULD APPEAR
THERE IS A DISCONTINUITY
BETWEEN THE TIME PERIODS YOU
DESCRIBED.
EVENTS IN ONE TIME PERIOD WOULD
HAVE NO EFFECT ON THE OTHER TWO.
YET IN BOTH
THE PAST AND THE PRESENT
THERE IS A REPORT OF THE SAME
ANOMALY IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
I FIND IT HARD TO BELIEVE THAT
THAT'S A COINCIDENCE.
FOR ALL I KNOW I MAY FIND THE
SAME THING IN THE FUTURE.
PERHAPS THE ANOMALY
IS A TEMPORAL DISTURBANCE
OF SOME KIND.
HOW IS ALL THIS RELATED
TO YOUR TIME SHIFTING?
THESE ARE ALL
VERY IMPORTANT QUESTIONS
AND PERHAPS I WILL FIND
ANSWERS TO THEM IN THE PAST
BUT NOW, WE HAVE
A POTENTIALLY DANGEROUS THREAT
FROM THE ROMULANS.
I WANT ALL DEPARTMENTS
TO PRESENT
A BATTLE READINESS
REPORT TO ME
AT 0800 HOURS
TOMORROW MORNING. DISMISSED.
Riker:
DEANNA...
IT'S GOING TO BE A LATE NIGHT.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO HAVE
SOME DINNER?
ACTUALLY, I...
WE HAVE PLANS.
OH, I SEE. I'M SORRY.
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE MORNING.
GOOD NIGHT, SIR.
WORF.
I WANT CONTINUAL
SUBSPACE SWEEPS.
WE MAY BE ABLE TO DETECT
A TEMPORAL DISTURBANCE.
AYE, SIR.
WILL...
THIS TIME SHIFTING--
WHEN IT HAPPENS, I EXPERIENCE
A MOMENTARY DISORIENTATION.
IF THAT SHOULD HAPPEN
DURING A CRISIS, WILL,
I WANT YOU TO TAKE COMMAND
IMMEDIATELY.
NUMBER ONE?
I'M SORRY.
BE PREPARED
TO TAKE COMMAND. AYE, SIR.
SPEAKING OF DISORIENTATION,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M JUST A LITTLE DISTRACTED.
I'M FINE.
( sighs )
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE,
NUMBER ONE.
I'LL... I'LL BE IN
MY READY ROOM.
( door chimes )
COME.
MILK, WARM.
A DASH OF NUTMEG.
WHAT'S THIS?
A PRESCRIPTION.
A GLASS OF WARM MILK
AND EIGHT HOURS'
UNINTERRUPTED SLEEP.
BEVERLY...
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
YOU'RE EXHAUSTED.
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
YOU SLEPT IN THE PAST
OR IN THE FUTURE,
BUT I'M SURE
YOU HAVEN'T SLEPT
IN THE PRESENT.
NOW, GET SOME REST,
OR I'LL HAVE YOU RELIEVED
AND SEDATED.
YES, SIR.
WHAT?
HEY.
BEVERLY?
AS A PHYSICIAN,
IT'S OFTEN MY JOB
TO GIVE PEOPLE
UNPLEASANT NEWS--
TO TELL THEM
THAT THEY NEED SURGERY
OR THAT THEY CAN'T
HAVE CHILDREN
OR THAT THEY MIGHT BE FACING
A DIFFICULT ILLNESS.
BUT YOU SAID YOURSELF
THAT THIS IS ONLY A POSSIBILITY.
BUT YOU'VE BEEN TO THE FUTURE.
YOU KNOW IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
I PREFER TO LOOK ON THE FUTURE
AS SOMETHING
WHICH IS NOT WRITTEN IN STONE.
A LOT OF THINGS CAN HAPPEN
IN 25 YEARS.
( tender theme playing )
A LOT OF THINGS
CAN HAPPEN.
( door hisses open and closed )
La Forge:
CAPTAIN?
YEAH?
La Forge:
CAPTAIN, WAKE UP.
YES.
WHAT IS IT?
HAVE WE REACHED
THE NEUTRAL ZONE?
La Forge:
OH... I'M SORRY.
I WAS IN THE PAST AGAIN.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
DATA'S ARRANGED FOR US
TO RUN THOSE TESTS ON YOU
IN THE BIOMETRICS LAB.
WE'RE READY TO GO
IF YOU ARE.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
WE HAVE TO GET
TO THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THE NEUTRAL ZONE? WHY?
IN THE OTHER
TWO TIME PERIODS
STARFLEET REPORTED... A...
A SORT OF A...
A SPATIAL ANOMALY
IN, IN, IN...
IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM
IN THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
CAPTAIN...
IF THE ANOMALY
APPEARED THERE IN THE PAST
THEN IT MIGHT BE HERE TOO,
AND WE HAVE TO FIND OUT.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'VE SEEN IT
IN TWO OTHER TIME FRAMES
DOESN'T MEAN THAT
IT'S GOING TO BE HERE.
YEAH, BUT IF IT IS HERE,
THEN IT MEANS SOMETHING!
DAMN IT, GEORDI,
I KNOW
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO!
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, BUT FIRST,
THERE IS NO NEUTRAL ZONE.
REMEMBER?
RIGHT.
RIGHT. KLINGONS.
IN THIS TIME PERIOD
THE KLINGONS HAVE TAKEN OVER
THE ROMULAN EMPIRE.
AND RIGHT NOW,
RELATIONS BETWEEN US
AND THE KLINGONS
AREN'T TOO COZY.
I KNOW THAT!
I HAVEN'T COMPLETELY
LOST MY MIND, YOU KNOW.
WELL, IF WE'RE GOING
TO THE DEVRON SYSTEM
WE'RE GOING TO NEED A SHIP.
( chuckling )
RIGHT.
NOW, I THINK IT'S TIME
TO CALL IN SOME OLD FAVORS.
CONTACT... ADMIRAL RIKER,
STARBASE 247.
Jean-Luc,
you know I'd like to help
but frankly, what you're asking
for is impossible.
The Klingons
have closed their borders
to all Federation starships.
WILL, WHAT IF
THIS SPATIAL ANOMALY
REALLY IS IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM?
I saw a report from Starfleet
Intelligence this morning
on that sector.
There is no activity.
There is nothing unusual
going on in the Devron System.
WELL, I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
WHAT IF THEIR
LONG-RANGE SCANS ARE FAULTY?
WE HAVE TO GO THERE
AND SEE FOR OURSELVES.
Look, I've got the Yorktown
out near the border.
I'll have her run
some long-range scans
on the Devron System.
If she finds out anything,
I'll let you know.
WILL, THAT IS JUST NOT GOOD
ENOUGH.
It's going to have to be.
I'm sorry.
It's all I can do.
Riker out.
COMPUTER, RESTORE
HOLOGRAPHIC IMAGE.
DAMN HIM ANYWAY.
AFTER ALL WE'VE
BEEN THROUGH TOGETHER.
HE'S BEEN SITTING
BEHIND THAT DESK TOO LONG.
CAPTAIN, I'M SORRY.
I GUESS ALL WE CAN DO NOW
IS WAIT AND SEE
IF THE YORKTOWN
FINDS ANYTHING.
THERE IS ANOTHER OPTION.
WE COULD
ARRANGE PASSAGE
ABOARD A MEDICAL SHIP.
MEDICAL SHIP?
YES, SIR.
THERE WAS AN OUTBREAK
OF TERRELLIAN PLAGUE ON ROMULUS.
THE KLINGONS HAVE BEEN ALLOWING
FEDERATION MEDICAL SHIPS
TO CROSS THE BORDER.
YES! YES!
SO, WHAT WE NEED NOW
IS A MEDICAL SHIP.
I THINK I CAN ARRANGE THAT.
DATA, FIND THE U.S.S. PASTEUR.
I...
I HAVE SOME PULL
WITH THE CAPTAIN.
AT LEAST, I USED TO HAVE.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door hisses open )
WELL, THIS IS A PAGE
FROM THE PAST.
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE EITHER OF YOU
ON A STARSHIP AGAIN.
HELLO, DOCTOR.
GEORDI.
DOCTOR.
DATA.
UH...
( laughs )
LET'S JUST CHOOSE ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
SO DID YOU GET MY MESSAGE?
YES. JEAN-LUC, CROSSING
INTO KLINGON TERRITORY--
IT'S ABSURD, BUT THEN,
I NEVER COULD SAY NO TO YOU.
OH, SO THAT'S WHY
YOU MARRIED ME.
WELL, NOW,
THE FIRST ORDER OF BUSINESS
IS TO GET CLEARANCE
TO CROSS
THE KLINGON BORDER.
AGREED. WHAT ABOUT WORF?
YES! THAT'S IT! WORF.
YES, THAT'S THE ANSWER.
WORF WILL HELP US.
DATA, ISN'T WORF STILL A MEMBER
OF THE KLINGON HIGH COUNCIL?
I'M NOT SURE.
INFORMATION ON THE KLINGON
POLITICAL STRUCTURE
IS HARD TO COME BY THESE DAYS.
HOWEVER, AT LAST REPORT,
WORF WAS GOVERNOR OF H'ATORIA
A SMALL KLINGON COLONY
NEAR THE BORDER.
CAPTAIN PICARD?
( beeping )
YES?
CAPTAIN, McKINLEY STATION
IS SIGNALING.
THEY WANT TO KNOW
WHEN WE'LL BE DOCKING.
TELL McKINLEY
WE'VE BEEN CALLED AWAY
ON A PRIORITY MISSION.
AYE, SIR.
SO YOU'VE KEPT
THE NAME.
I'VE PREPARED QUARTERS FOR YOU
ON DECK FIVE.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO GET SOME REST.
NO I'M FINE, I DON'T NEED REST.
NELL, PLEASE ESCORT
THE AMBASSADOR
TO HIS QUARTERS.
LOOK, YOU ARE TREATING ME
AS IF I AM AN INVALID.
I DO HAVE A FEW YEARS
LEFT IN ME YET.
I DO NOT WANT
TO BE LED AROUND
AND I DO NOT
WANT TO BE PATRONIZED.
YOU'RE RIGHT. I'M SORRY.
NOW, I'LL GO
AND GET SOME REST.
HOW LONG SINCE
HIS LAST NEUROLOGICAL SCAN?
I'M NOT SURE.
BUT I WOULDN'T TRY
SUGGESTING IT.
HE SAYS HE'S NOT TAKING
ANY MORE DAMN TESTS.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
HE'S MOVING THROUGH TIME?
I'M NOT SURE I DO EITHER.
BUT HE'S JEAN-LUC PICARD,
AND IF HE WANTS TO GO
ON ONE MORE MISSION
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
WE'LL FIND THE ANOMALY.
I KNOW WE WILL.
REPORT.
WE'RE NEARING THE COORDINATES
YOU GAVE ME, SIR.
IS THERE ANYTHING UNUSUAL
IN THE VICINITY, MR. DATA?
HOW WOULD YOU DEFINE
"UNUSUAL," SIR?
EVERY REGION OF SPACE
HAS ITS OWN UNIQUE PROPERTIES
THAT CANNOT BE FOUND
ANYWHERE ELSE.
THERE SHOULD BE
A BARRIER OF SOME SORT NEARBY--
A LARGE PLASMA FIELD,
HIGHLY DISRUPTIVE.
NOTHING, SIR.
THIS IS THE RIGHT TIME,
THE RIGHT PLACE.
HE SHOULD BE HERE NOW.
WHO, SIR?
Q! WE'RE HERE.
THIS HAS GONE ON LONG ENOUGH.
COUNSELOR, DO YOU SENSE
AN ALIEN PRESENCE?
NO, SIR.
WHAT IS A "Q?"
IT'S A LETTER
OF THE ALPHABET
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
Picard:
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS NOT THE WAY
IT'S SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN.
MAINTAIN THIS POSITION.
I'LL BE IN MY READY ROOM.
( all yelling )
( crowd falls silent )
MON CAPITAN.
I THOUGHT YOU'D NEVER GET HERE.
Q, I KNEW IT.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'S JUDGE Q TO YOU.
AND ISN'T IT OBVIOUS
WHAT'S GOING ON?
( crowd laughing )
THE LAST TIME
THAT I STOOD HERE
WAS SEVEN YEARS AGO.
SEVEN YEARS AGO?
HOW LITTLE DO YOU MORTALS
UNDERSTAND TIME.
MUST YOU BE SO LINEAR, JEAN-LUC?
YOU ACCUSED ME
OF BEING THE REPRESENTATIVE
OF A... A BARBAROUS SPECIES.
I BELIEVE MY EXACT WORDS WERE,
"A DANGEROUS,
SAVAGE, CHILD-RACE."
( laughter )
WE DEMONSTRATED TO YOU
THAT MANKIND HAD BECOME
PEACEFUL AND BENEVOLENT.
YOU AGREED
AND YOU LET US GO ON OUR WAY.
NOW WHY AM I STANDING HERE
AGAIN?
OH, YOU'D LIKE ME
TO CONNECT THE DOTS FOR YOU--
LEAD YOU FROM "A" TO "B" TO "C"
SO THAT YOUR PUNY MIND
COULD COMPREHEND.
HOW BORING.
( laughter )
THEY'D BE
SO MUCH MORE ENTERTAINED
IF YOU JUST TRIED
TO FIGURE IT OUT.
I'LL ANSWER
ANY TEN QUESTIONS THAT CALL
FOR A "YES" OR A "NO."
( cheering )
WELL?
ARE YOU PUTTING MANKIND
ON TRIAL AGAIN?
NO.
YEAH, YEAH!
IS THERE ANY CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE TRIAL
SEVEN YEARS AGO
AND WHAT'S HAPPENING NOW?
I'D HAVE TO SAY YES.
YEAH, YEAH!
THE SPATIAL ANOMALY
IN THE NEUTRAL ZONE--
IS IT RELATED
TO WHAT'S GOING ON?
MOST DEFINITELY YES.
IS IT PART
OF A ROMULAN PLOT--
A PLOY TO START A WAR?
NO AND NO.
FIVE DOWN!
THAT'S ONLY FOUR.
IS IT A ROMULAN PLOT?
IS IT A PLOY TO START A WAR?
THOSE ARE
SEPARATE QUESTIONS.
DID YOU CREATE THE ANOMALY?
NO, NO, NO.
( laughing ):
YOU'RE GOING TO BE SO SURPRISED
WHEN YOU REALIZE
WHERE IT CAME FROM...
IF YOU EVER FIGURE IT OUT.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR MY SHIFTING THROUGH TIME?
I'LL ANSWER THAT QUESTION
IF YOU PROMISE
YOU WON'T TELL ANYONE.
YES.
WHY?
SORRY! THAT'S NOT A "YES"
OR A "NO" QUESTION.
YOU FORFEIT THE REST
OF YOUR QUESTIONS.
( booing )
CHEATER!
I EXPECTED AS MUCH.
YOU'RE SUCH
A LIMITED CREATURE--
A PERFECT EXAMPLE
OF WHY WE MADE OUR DECISION.
THE TRIAL NEVER ENDED, CAPTAIN.
WE NEVER REACHED A VERDICT.
BUT NOW WE HAVE.
YOU'RE GUILTY.
GUILTY OF WHAT?
OF BEING INFERIOR.
SEVEN YEARS AGO,
I SAID WE'D BE WATCHING YOU,
AND WE HAVE BEEN,
HOPING THAT
YOUR APE-LIKE RACE
WOULD DEMONSTRATE SOME GROWTH,
GIVE SOME INDICATION
THAT YOUR MINDS
HAD ROOM FOR EXPANSION.
BUT WHAT HAVE WE SEEN INSTEAD?
YOU WORRYING ABOUT
COMMANDER RIKER'S CAREER,
LISTENING TO COUNSELOR TROI'S
PEDANTIC PSYCHO-BABBLE,
INDULGING DATA
IN HIS WITLESS
EXPLORATION OF HUMANITY.
WE'VE JOURNEYED TO COUNTLESS
NEW WORLDS.
WE'VE CONTACTED NEW SPECIES.
WE HAVE EXPANDED
OUR UNDERSTANDING
OF THE UNIVERSE.
IN YOUR OWN PALTRY, LIMITED WAY.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW FAR YOU HAVE TO GO.
BUT INSTEAD OF USING
THE LAST SEVEN YEARS
TO CHANGE AND TO GROW,
YOU HAVE SQUANDERED THEM.
WE ARE WHAT WE ARE,
AND WE'RE DOING THE BEST WE CAN.
IT IS NOT FOR YOU
TO SET THE STANDARDS
BY WHICH
WE SHOULD BE JUDGED.
OH, BUT IT IS, AND WE HAVE.
TIME MAY BE ETERNAL, CAPTAIN,
BUT OUR PATIENCE IS NOT.
IT'S TIME TO PUT AN END
TO YOUR TREK THROUGH THE STARS,
MAKE ROOM FOR OTHER
MORE WORTHY SPECIES.
YOU'RE GOING TO DENY US
TRAVEL THROUGH SPACE?
NO...
( laughter )
YOU OBTUSE PIECE OF FLOTSAM.
YOU'RE TO BE DENIED EXISTENCE.
HUMANITY'S FATE HAS BEEN SEALED.
YOU WILL BE DESTROYED.
Q, I DO NOT BELIEVE
THAT EVEN YOU
ARE CAPABLE OF SUCH AN ACT.
AYE. THERE YOU GO AGAIN,
ALWAYS BLAMING ME
FOR EVERYTHING.
WELL, THIS TIME,
I'M NOT YOUR ENEMY.
I'M NOT THE ONE THAT CAUSES
THE ANNIHILATION OF MANKIND.
YOU ARE.
ME?
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE DOING IT RIGHT NOW.
YOU DID IT BEFORE,
AND YOU'LL DO IT YET AGAIN.
WHAT SORT OF MEANINGLESS
DOUBLE-TALK IS THIS?
HE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
( laughter )
I HAVE ONLY MYSELF
TO BLAME, I SUPPOSE.
I BELIEVED IN YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD POTENTIAL
BUT, APPARENTLY,
I WAS WRONG.
MAY WHATEVER GOD
YOU BELIEVE IN...
HAVE MERCY ON YOUR SOUL.
THIS COURT STANDS ADJOURNED.
( gong sounds )
COMMANDER, ASSEMBLE
THE SENIOR STAFF
AND GO TO RED ALERT.
WE HAVE A BIGGER PROBLEM
THAN I THOUGHT.
RED ALERT!
( alarm blares )
I DON'T BELIEVE HIM. THIS HAS TO
BE ANOTHER ONE OF Q's GAMES.
HE'S PROBABLY LISTENING
TO US RIGHT NOW
GETTING A BIG LAUGH
OUT OF WATCHING US
JUMP THROUGH HIS HOOPS.
NORMALLY, I WOULD AGREE WITH YOU
BUT THIS TIME I FEEL
THAT SOMEHOW IT IS DIFFERENT.
THERE WAS A DEADLY EARNESTNESS
ABOUT HIM.
I THINK HE'S SERIOUS...
WHICH MEANS
THAT IN SOME FASHION,
I AM GOING TO BE THE CAUSE
OF THE DESTRUCTION OF HUMANITY.
BUT DIDN'T Q SAY
YOU ALREADY HAD CAUSED IT?
AND THAT YOU
WERE CAUSING IT NOW?
GIVEN THAT THERE IS
AN APPARENT DISCONTINUITY
BETWEEN THE THREE TIME PERIODS
THE CAPTAIN HAS VISITED,
Q's STATEMENT
MAY BE ACCURATE, IF CONFUSING.
SO, WHAT AM I GOING TO DO?
LOCK MYSELF IN A ROOM
IN ALL THE THREE
DIFFERENT TIME PERIODS?
CAPTAIN. MAYBE NOT ACTING
IS WHAT CAUSES
THE DESTRUCTION OF MANKIND.
WHAT IF YOU WERE NEEDED
ON THE BRIDGE
AT A KEY MOMENT
AND YOU WEREN'T THERE?
I DON'T THINK WE CAN START
SECOND-GUESSING OURSELVES.
I THINK WE HAVE
TO PROCEED NORMALLY
AND DEAL WITH EACH SITUATION
AS IT OCCURS.
AGREED. I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT MY CONVERSATION WITH Q.
HE ADMITTED
THAT HE WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR MY SHIFTING THROUGH TIME.
NOW IT OCCURRED TO ME...
THAT HE MIGHT BE GIVING ME A
CHANCE SOMEHOW TO SAVE HUMANITY.
WHAT MAKES YOU SAY THAT?
WELL, HE'S ALWAYS HAD
A FASCINATION WITH HUMANITY
WITH MYSELF,
IN PARTICULAR.
I THINK HE HAS MORE THAN
A PASSING INTEREST
IN WHAT HAPPENS TO ME.
Data:
THAT IS TRUE.
Q's INTEREST IN YOU HAS ALWAYS
BEEN VERY SIMILAR
TO THAT OF A MASTER
AND HIS BELOVED PET.
THAT WAS ONLY
AN ANALOGY, CAPTAIN.
Captain Picard.
GO AHEAD.
We're approaching
the Neutral Zone, Captain.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
ALL STOP.
INITIATE LONG-RANGE SCANS.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE FOUR WARBIRDS
HOLDING POSITION
ON THE ROMULAN SIDE
OF THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THE FEDERATION STARSHIPS
CONCORD AND BOZEMAN
ARE HOLDING POSITION
ON OUR SIDE.
A FACE-OFF.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHO'S GOING TO BE FIRST?
WE ARE.
MR. WORF,
HAIL THE ROMULAN FLAGSHIP.
Worf:
THE WARBIRD TERIX IS RESPONDING.
Captain Picard.
HELLO, WORF.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME.
It is good to see you again.
HAVE YOU HAD A CHANCE
TO READ OUR REQUEST?
Yes, but you must realize
I am no longer a member
of the High Council.
BUT SURELY WORF YOU MUST STILL
HAVE SOME INFLUENCE.
WE HAVE TO GET
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
CAN'T YOU JUST GET US PERMISSION
TO CROSS THE BORDER?
I must refuse.
It is for your own safety.
The Neutral Zone
is extremely volatile.
If Admiral Riker had given you
a starship with a cloak
you would have been safe.
It is hard to believe
that even he would refuse
to help you.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT KIND OF SHIP WE GO IN!
WE HAVE TO GET
TO THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
I am sorry.
My first duty is to the Empire.
I must adhere to regulations.
WELL, I KNOW
THAT I'M AN OLD MAN
AND I'M OUT OF TOUCH
BUT THE WORF
THAT I REMEMBER
WAS MORE CONCERNED
WITH THINGS
LIKE HONOR AND LOYALTY
THAN RULES
AND REGULATIONS.
BUT THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
MAYBE YOU'RE NOT THE WORF
I ONCE KNEW.
Dor-sHo GHA!
You have always used
your knowledge
of Klingon honor and tradition
to get what you want from me.
BECAUSE IT ALWAYS WORKS, WORF!
YOUR PROBLEM IS THAT YOU
REALLY DO HAVE A SENSE OF HONOR
AND YOU REALLY DO CARE
ABOUT TRUST AND LOYALTY.
DON'T BLAME ME
FOR KNOWING YOU SO WELL.
Very well.
You may cross the border.
But...
only if I come with you.
I am familiar
with the Neutral Zone.
TERMS ACCEPTED.
INFORM TRANSPORTER ROOM TWO
TO BEAM THE GOVERNOR ABOARD.
I MUST MAKE ONE THING
VERY CLEAR, JEAN-LUC.
IF WE RUN
INTO SERIOUS OPPOSITION
I'M TAKING US BACK
INTO FEDERATION TERRITORY.
WE AREN'T WELL-ARMED
AND WOULDN'T LAST LONG
IN A FIGHT.
GOVERNOR WORF
IS ABOARD, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
SET COURSE
FOR THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
WARP 13.
ONCE MORE,
FOR OLD TIME'S SAKE?
ENGAGE.
ENGAGE TO WHERE, SIR?
UH, SET A COURSE
FOR THE DEVRON SYSTEM
AND ENGAGE AT WARP NINE.
THE DEVRON SYSTEM IS INSIDE
THE NEUTRAL ZONE, SIR.
I'M AWARE OF THAT, LIEUTENANT.
CARRY OUT MY ORDERS, CHIEF.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN,
MAY I HAVE
A WORD WITH YOU IN PRIVATE?
YES OF COURSE, COUNSELOR.
CONTACT FARPOINT STATION.
I WISH TO SPEAK
WITH COMMANDER RIKER.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I JUST WANTED
TO VOICE MY CONCERNS
ABOUT THE WAY
THE CREW IS RESPONDING
TO YOUR UNEXPECTED ORDERS.
THEY DON'T TRUST ME.
THEY THINK
THAT I'M BEHAVING ERRATICALLY.
SOME DO. OTHERS ARE CONFUSED.
IT TAKES SOME TIME
FOR A NEW CREW
TO GET TO KNOW THEIR CAPTAIN
AND FOR HIM TO KNOW THEM.
I UNDERSTAND,
BUT I ALSO KNOW
WHAT THIS CREW IS CAPABLE OF
EVEN IF THEY DON'T.
IT WOULD ALSO HELP
IF THEY KNEW WHAT WAS GOING ON.
I KNOW IT'S DIFFICULT
OPERATING IN THE DARK
BUT RIGHT NOW, I DON'T THINK
I HAVE ANY OTHER CHOICE.
Tasha:
Yar to Captain Picard.
I have Commander Riker
for you, sir.
EXCUSE ME.
PUT HIM THROUGH HERE.
COMMANDER RIKER,
I WANTED TO INFORM YOU
THAT WE WILL BE DELAYED PICKING
YOU UP AT FARPOINT STATION.
I see. May I ask how long?
I CAN'T SAY.
I'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED.
WILL YOU INFORM DR. CRUSHER
AND LIEUTENANT La FORGE
OF OUR DELAY?
Understood. Riker out.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE,
COUNSELOR?
ACTUALLY, SIR, THERE IS.
I WAS DEBATING
WHETHER TO MENTION IT
AND PERHAPS...
IT'S ABOUT COMMANDER RIKER.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
I THINK YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT HE AND I HAVE HAD A...
PRIOR RELATIONSHIP.
I SEE.
DO YOU THINK THIS WILL
INTERFERE WITH YOUR DUTIES?
NOT AT ALL.
IT HAPPENED SEVERAL YEARS AGO,
AND IT'S WELL BEHIND
BOTH OF US NOW.
I JUST THOUGHT YOU SHOULD KNOW.
I APPRECIATE
YOUR TELLING ME.
WELL, I'M QUITE SURE THAT THE
TWO OF YOU WILL FIND SOME WAY
TO DEAL
WITH THE SITUATION.
THANK YOU, SIR.
TEA, EARL GREY, HOT.
Beverage Maker:
That beverage
has not been programmed
into the replication system.
So, Captain,
how long shall
we stare at each other
across the Neutral Zone?
THERE IS AN ALTERNATIVE,
TOMOLAK.
WE EACH KNOW
WHY WE'RE HERE.
WE COULD EACH SEND ONE SHIP
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
TO INVESTIGATE THE ANOMALY
IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
Has Starfleet Command
approved this arrangement?
NO.
I like it already.
Agreed.
One ship from each side.
But I warn you,
if another Federation starship
tries to enter the zone...
THERE IS NO NEED TO MAKE
THREATS.
WE EACH KNOW THE CONSEQUENCES.
Very well.
I'll see you
in the Devron system.
HELM, SET A COURSE
FOR THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
WARP FIVE.
Helm: AYE, SIR.
ENGAGE.
( dramatic theme playing )
SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
A LARGE SUBSPACE ANOMALY
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
ALL STOP.
ON SCREEN.
FULL SCAN, MR. DATA.
Data:
AYE, SIR.
Picard:
WE HAVE TO GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE
ABOUT THAT ANOMALY.
WE ARE APPROACHING
THE DEVRON SYSTEM, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
A LARGE SUBSPACE ANOMALY
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
ALL STOP. ON SCREEN.
AND IT IS LARGER IN THE PAST.
SIR?
NOTHING.
FULL SCAN, MR. DATA.
Data:
AYE, SIR.
ON SCREEN! ON SCREEN!
LET'S SEE IT!
AS YOU CAN SEE, SIR,
THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
STILL NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
I'VE CONDUCTED A FULL SENSOR
SWEEP
OUT TO ONE LIGHT-YEAR
FROM THE PASTEUR.
NO TEMPORAL ANOMALIES, NO
PARTICLE FLUCTUATIONS, NOTHING.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND. IT WAS HERE
IN THE OTHER TWO TIME PERIODS.
WHY ISN'T IT HERE NOW?
Worf:
CAPTAIN, I HAVE BEEN MONITORING
KLINGON COMMUNICATIONS CHANNELS.
SEVERAL WARSHIPS
HAVE BEEN DISPATCHED
TO THIS SECTOR TO SEARCH FOR
A RENEGADE
FEDERATION VESSEL.
YOU'RE NOT THINKING OF LEAVING?
THERE'S NOTHING HERE, JEAN-LUC.
BUT THERE SHOULD BE.
THERE HAS TO BE!
DATA, IS THERE
SOME OTHER WAY
TO SCAN FOR
TEMPORAL DISTURBANCES?
SOMETHING THAT ISN'T COVERED
IN A NORMAL SENSOR SWEEP?
THERE ARE SEVERAL METHODS OF
DETECTING TEMPORAL DISTURBANCES
BUT WE'RE LIMITED
BY THE EQUIPMENT ON THE PASTEUR.
WE SHOULD HEAD BACK
TO FEDERATION TERRITORY.
HOWEVER, IT MAY BE POSSIBLE
TO MODIFY THE MAIN DEFLECTOR
TO EMIT
AN INVERSE TACHYON PULSE
WHICH COULD SCAN
BEYOND THE SUBSPACE BARRIER.
THAT'S IT.
MAKE IT SO.
WAIT A MINUTE.
DATA, HOW LONG
WOULD THIS TAKE?
TO MAKE THE MODIFICATIONS AND
SEARCH THE ENTIRE DEVRON SYSTEM
WOULD TAKE
APPROXIMATELY 14 HOURS.
ALRIGHT DATA, BEGIN TO MODIFY
THE TACHYON PULSE.
ENSIGN CHILTON,
LAY IN A COURSE
BACK TO THE FEDERATION.
WE'LL STAY HERE
FOR SIX MORE HOURS.
AND IF WE HAVEN'T FOUND ANYTHING
WE'RE HEADING BACK,
MAXIMUM WARP.
AYE, SIR.
BUT SIX MORE HOURS
MAY NOT BE ENOUGH.
WE HAVE TO STAY
UNTIL WE FIND IT
NO MATTER
HOW LONG IT TAKES.
CARRY OUT MY ORDERS.
MAY I SEE YOU A MOMENT?
BEVERLY,
I CANNOT BELIEVE
THAT YOU ARE NOT WILLING
TO STAY HERE UNTIL--
DON'T YOU EVER
QUESTION MY ORDERS
ON THE BRIDGE OF MY SHIP AGAIN.
DAMN IT!
I WAS JUST TRYING TO...
LOOK,
THERE ARE
LARGER CONCERNS HERE.
WHAT YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND IS--
I UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU WOULD NEVER
HAVE TOLERATED
THAT KIND OF BEHAVIOR
BACK ON THE ENTERPRISE,
AND I WON'T HERE.
I DON'T CARE
IF YOU'RE MY EX-CAPTAIN
OR MY EX-HUSBAND.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I WAS OUT OF LINE.
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
BUT WHAT YOU HAVE
TO UNDERSTAND IS
WHAT IS AT STAKE HERE.
Q HAS SAID THAT ALL OF HUMANITY
WILL BE DESTROYED.
I KNOW.
THAT'S WHY I'VE ALLOWED US
TO STAY HERE LONGER
AND KEEP LOOKING.
BUT I ALSO WANT YOU
TO ALLOW FOR THE POSSIBILITY
THAT NONE OF WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING IS REAL.
WHAT?
JEAN-LUC,
I CARE FOR YOU TOO MUCH
NOT TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
YOU HAVE
ADVANCED IRUMODIC SYNDROME.
IT'S POSSIBLE THAT ALL
OF THIS IS IN YOUR MIND.
I'LL STAY HERE
SIX HOURS LONGER,
AND THEN WE'RE HEADING HOME.
I WANT YOU
TO REMEMBER,
IF IT WERE
ANYONE ELSE BUT YOU,
WE WOULDN'T
EVEN BE HERE.
EH? WHAT WAS THAT
SHE SAID, SONNY?
I COULDN'T QUITE HEAR HER.
Q, WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
WHERE IS THE ANOMALY?
WHERE'S YOUR MOMMY?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
ANSWER ME!
THERE IS AN ANSWER, JEAN-LUC,
BUT I CAN'T
HAND IT TO YOU.
ALTHOUGH YOU
DO HAVE HELP.
WHAT HELP?
YOU'RE NOT ALONE,
YOU KNOW.
WHAT YOU WERE
AND WHAT YOU
ARE TO BECOME
WILL ALWAYS BE WITH YOU.
MY TIME SHIFTING...
THE ANSWER DOES LIE THERE,
DOESN'T IT?
NOW, TELL ME ONE THING.
THIS ANOMALY
WE'RE LOOKING FOR
WILL THAT DESTROY HUMANITY?
YOU'RE FORGETTING,
JEAN-LUC.
YOU DESTROY
HUMANITY.
BY DOING WHAT?
WHEN?
HOW CAN--?
( beeping )
REPORT, MR. DATA.
THE ANOMALY IS
200 MILLION KILOMETERS
IN DIAMETER.
IT IS A HIGHLY FOCUSED
TEMPORAL ENERGY SOURCE
WHICH IS EMITTING APPROXIMATELY
THE SAME ENERGY OUTPUT
AS TEN G-TYPE STARS.
WHAT IS THE SOURCE
OF THIS ENERGY?
I AM UNCERTAIN, SIR.
SENSORS ARE UNABLE
TO PENETRATE THE ANOMALY.
WHAT IF WE MODIFIED
THE MAIN DEFLECTOR
TO EMIT AN INVERSE
TACHYON PULSE
THAT MIGHT BE ABLE TO SCAN
BEYOND THE SUBSPACE BARRIER?
THAT MIGHT GIVE US SOME IDEA OF
WHAT THE INTERIOR OF THIS THING
LOOKS LIKE.
THAT IS A MOST INTRIGUING IDEA,
SIR.
I DO NOT BELIEVE A TACHYON BEAM
WAS EVER USED IN SUCH A WAY.
I HAD NO IDEA YOU WERE SO VERSED
IN THE INTRICACIES
OF TEMPORAL THEORIES.
I HAVE SOME FRIENDS
WHO ARE WELL VERSED IN IT.
MAKE IT SO.
I BELIEVE WE CAN MAKE
THE NECESSARY MODIFICATIONS
IN MAIN
ENGINEERING, SIR.
WE CAN GET MORE POWER
IF WE REROUTE
THE PRIMARY E.P.S. TAPS
TO THE DEFLECTOR ARRAY.
AGREED.
INITIATING TACHYON PULSE.
OKAY.
THE PULSE IS HOLDING STEADY.
WE'RE STARTING TO RECEIVE DATA
FROM THE SCAN.
IT WILL TAKE THE COMPUTER
SOME TIME TO GIVE US
A COMPLETE PICTURE
OF THE ANOMALY'S INTERIOR.
( groaning )
GEORDI,
WHAT IS WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S LIKE SOMEBODY'S STICKING
AN ICE PICK IN MY TEMPLES.
MY VISOR'S PICKING UP
ALL KINDS OF ELECTROMAGNETIC
FLUCTUATIONS.
DATA TO SICK BAY.
MEDICAL EMERGENCY
IN MAIN ENGINEERING.
Beverly:
THIS IS AMAZING.
THE DNA IN HIS OPTIC NERVES
IS REGENERATING.
GEORDI, IT'S AS IF
YOU'RE GROWING
NEW EYES.
HOW IS THIS POSSIBLE?
IT SHOULDN'T BE POSSIBLE AT ALL.
THERE'S NO
MEDICAL EXPLANATION
FOR SPONTANEOUS REGENERATION
OF AN ORGAN.
DOCTOR, WE'VE JUST GOTTEN
REPORTS FROM TWO CREW MEMBERS
WHO SAY THEY HAVE OLD SCARS
WHICH ARE HEALING
THEMSELVES.
CAPTAIN, I BELIEVE
I HAVE A PARTIAL EXPLANATION.
I'VE COMPLETED MY ANALYSIS
OF THE ANOMALY.
IT APPEARS TO BE A MULTI-PHASIC
TEMPORAL CONVERGENCE
IN THE SPACE-TIME CONTINUUM.
IN ENGLISH, DATA.
IT IS, IN ESSENCE,
AN ERUPTION OF ANTI-TIME.
ANTI-TIME?
A RELATIVELY NEW CONCEPT
IN TEMPORAL MECHANICS.
THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN
ANTI-TIME AND NORMAL TIME
IS ANALOGOUS
TO THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN ANTI-MATTER
AND NORMAL MATTER.
SO IF TIME AND ANTI-TIME
WERE TO COLLIDE...?
THEY WOULD ANNIHILATE
ONE ANOTHER,
CAUSING A RUPTURE
IN SPACE.
I BELIEVE THIS IS
WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
THE RUPTURE
MAY BE SENDING OUT
WAVES OF TEMPORAL ENERGY
WHICH ARE DISRUPTING
THE NORMAL FLOW OF TIME.
DATA, WHAT COULD HAVE CAUSED
THIS COLLISION
OF TIME AND ANTI-TIME?
ANTI-TIME, SIR?
I BELIEVE THAT IF YOU MODIFY
THE DEFLECTORS TO SEND OUT
AN INVERSE TACHYON PULSE,
THEN YOU'LL FIND
THAT THE ANOMALY IS A RUPTURE
BETWEEN TIME AND ANTI-TIME.
THAT IS
A FASCINATING HYPOTHESIS.
HOW DID YOU--?
I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO DISCUSS IT NOW, MR. DATA.
DO THE MODIFICATIONS
AND SEND OUT THE PULSE.
THEN TRY WORKING ON A THEORY
AS TO WHAT CAUSED THIS RUPTURE.
MR. O'BRIEN,
HOW LARGE IS THIS ANOMALY?
APPROXIMATELY 400 MILLION
KILOMETERS IN DIAMETER, SIR.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY IT'S BIGGER
IN THE PAST.
LIEUTENANT, YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
I'LL BE IN MY READY ROOM.
AYE, SIR.
Picard:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
Beverly:
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
SHIELDS STRAIGHT DOWN
TO 52 PERCENT.
MINOR DAMAGE
TO THE PORT NACELLE.
TWO KLINGON
ATTACK CRUISERS
DECLOAKING
TO PORT AND STARBOARD.
WARP SPEED.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
WARP POWER'S OFF-LINE, SIR.
HEADING 1-4-8, MARK 2-1-5. FULL
IMPULSE.
IMPULSE POWERS
FLUCTUATING.
SHIELDS DOWN TO 30 PERCENT.
WEAPONS STATUS.
THESE WEAPONS ARE NO MATCH
FOR THEIR SHIELDS.
GEORDI, WE NEED MORE WARP
POWER-- NOW.
I'M TRYING, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE TOO MUCH FOR US.
I CAN'T KEEP
THE PHASE INDUCERS ONLINE.
SHIELDS DOWN TO 9 PERCENT.
ONE MORE HIT,
AND THEY'LL COLLAPSE.
OPEN A CHANNEL.
OPEN.
THIS IS CAPTAIN BEVERLY PICARD.
WE ARE A MEDICAL SHIP
ON A MISSION OF MERCY.
PLEASE BREAK OFF ALL...
WORF, SIGNAL OUR SURRENDER.
tOS vAH'CHA DO WORF.
DO'LO JEGH!
( dramatic theme playing )
( explosion )
OUR SHIELDS HAVE COLLAPSED.
WE ARE DEFENSELESS.
CAPTAIN, ANOTHER SHIP
IS DECLOAKING,
BEARING 2-1-5,
MARK 3-1-0.
IT'S THE ENTERPRISE.
THEY'RE HAILING US.
Beverly:
ON SCREEN.
I had a feeling you weren't
going listen to me. Stand by.
I'll see if I can get
the Klingons' attention.
( dramatic theme playing )
THE ENTERPRISE IS DRAWING
THEIR FIRE.
DAMAGE REPORT.
THE WARP CORE
HAS BEEN BADLY DAMAGED.
THERE'S A BREACH
IN PROGRESS.
WE HAVE TO STOP IT.
Data:
THE KLINGON SHIP
IS DISENGAGING.
ADMIRAL RIKER
IS HAILING US.
Our sensors indicate
your ship has a warp core
breach in progress.
Prepare for emergency beam-out.
ALL THE PASTEUR'S CREW
IS SAFELY ONBOARD, ADMIRAL.
RAISE THE SHIELDS.
WHERE ARE THE KLINGONS?
THEY'RE STILL
MOVING OFF, SIR.
HALF A LIGHT-YEAR AWAY.
THEY'LL BE BACK.
AS I SAID I FIGURED YOU WOULDN'T
TAKE NO FOR AN ANSWER.
BUT I THOUGHT YOU
HAD MORE SENSE
THAN TO SEND A DEFENSELESS SHIP
ACROSS THE BORDER
INTO HOSTILE TERRITORY
WITH NO ESCORT.
IF YOU HAD NOT
TURNED DOWN THE CAPTAIN
WHEN HE CAME TO YOU FOR HELP,
NONE OF THIS
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED!
BUT UNLIKE YOU,
I STILL HAVE A SENSE
OF HONOR AND LOYALTY.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME FOR THIS!
THE PASTEUR'S CORE
IS GOING TO BREACH!
TAKE US OUT OF HERE
AT FULL IMPULSE.
( dramatic theme playing )
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
NO, WILL, WE CAN'T!
WE HAVE TO SAVE HUMANITY!
ENGAGE CLOAK.
Man:
ADMIRAL, WE TOOK A DIRECT HIT
TO THE STARBOARD
PLASMA COIL.
OUR CLOAK ISN'T FUNCTIONING.
ENGINEERING REPORTS IT'LL BE
SEVEN HOURS
BEFORE WE CAN CLOAK AGAIN.
Riker:
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL DO IT
THE OLD-FASHION WAY.
SET A COURSE FOR
FEDERATION SPACE, WARP 13.
WILL, DON'T LEAVE.
WE HAVE TO STAY HERE
AND FIND OUT WHAT IS CAUSING
THE TEMPORAL ANOMALY!
WE CAN'T STAY, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE TO--
EVERYTHING DEPENDS ON IT.
WE CAN'T LEAVE NOW.
PLEASE, LISTEN TO ME!
( indistinct chattering )
YOUR VISUAL ACUITY IS
IMPROVING BY THE HOUR, GEORDI.
( computer beeps )
I'M SORRY, ALISSA.
MAY I TAKE ANOTHER LOOK?
YOU'LL HAVE A LITTLE TENDERNESS
FOR A FEW DAYS.
THAT'S TO BE EXPECTED.
JEAN-LUC.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK,
ALISSA.
ALISSA LOST THE BABY.
I THINK
IT'S THE SAME PHENOMENON
THAT AFFECTED GEORDI.
SOMEHOW THE TEMPORAL ENERGY
FROM THE ANOMALY
CAUSED THE FETAL TISSUE
TO REVERT
TO AN EARLIER STAGE
OF DEVELOPMENT.
IT'S AS IF THE UNBORN CHILD
BEGAN TO GROW YOUNGER
UNTIL FINALLY THE DNA ITSELF
BEGAN TO BREAK DOWN.
HOW IS SHE?
PHYSICALLY,
SHE'S FINE, FOR NOW.
BUT IF THIS
TEMPORAL REVERSION CONTINUES
I DON'T THINK ANY OF US ARE
GOING TO BE FINE
FOR MUCH LONGER.
SO THIS IS AFFECTING
THE ENTIRE CREW.
OUR CELLULAR STRUCTURES
APPEAR TO BE COALESCING--
REVERTING TO EARLIER FORMS.
IN SOME CASES
THIS HAS CAUSED
OLD INJURIES TO BE HEALED
BUT THE EFFECT
IS ONLY TEMPORARY.
EVENTUALLY,
IT MAY KILL ALL OF US.
WE HAVE TO DETERMINE
HOW WIDESPREAD THIS EFFECT IS.
CONTACT STARBASE 23.
THAT'S THE NEWEST OUTPOST.
HAVE THEM CHECK
THEIR PERSONNEL
TO SEE IF THERE ARE ANY SIGNS
OF TEMPORAL REVERSION.
AYE, SIR.
MR. DATA, HOW CLOSE ARE YOU TO
COMPLETING THE TACHYON SCAN?
APPROXIMATELY ONE HOUR,
45 MINUTES, SIR.
GOOD. WHEN IT'S DONE,
I WANT YOU TO FIND SOME WAY OF
COLLAPSING THIS ANOMALY
WITHOUT MAKING THINGS WORSE.
GIVE ME A RISK ANALYSIS
OF WHATEVER SOLUTION
YOU COME UP WITH.
AYE, SIR.
DISMISSED.
( door hisses open and closed )
Q:
IT'S A PRETTY BIG DECISION,
JEAN-LUC.
TINKERING WITH AN ANOMALY
YOU KNOW NOTHING ABOUT.
TRYING TO COLLAPSE IT.
ISN'T THAT RISKY?
WHY? WILL THAT CAUSE
THE DESTRUCTION OF MANKIND?
MAYBE.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
MAYBE LEAVING IT ALONE
WOULD BE THE WRONG
THING TO DO.
IT'S A PRETTY BIG DECISION,
ALL RIGHT.
WOULD IT HELP TO HAVE
A DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVE?
Q:
WELCOME HOME.
HOME?
DON'T YOU RECOGNIZE
YOUR OLD STOMPING GROUNDS?
THIS IS EARTH--
FRANCE, ABOUT OH
3 1/2 BILLION YEARS AGO,
GIVE OR TAKE AN EON OR TWO.
SMELLS AWFUL, DOESN'T IT?
ALL THAT SULFUR
AND VOLCANIC ASH.
I REALLY MUST SPEAK
TO THE MAID.
Q, IS THERE ANY POINT
TO ALL THIS?
LOOK.
Picard:
SO THE ANOMALY IS HERE TOO.
AT EARTH.
Q:
AT THIS POINT IN HISTORY
THE ANOMALY FILLS
YOUR ENTIRE QUADRANT
OF THE GALAXY.
THE FURTHER BACK IN TIME...
THE LARGER THE ANOMALY.
COME HERE.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I WANT TO SHOW YOU.
YOU SEE THIS?
THIS IS YOU.
I'M SERIOUS.
RIGHT HERE...
LIFE IS ABOUT TO FORM
ON THIS PLANET
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME.
A GROUP OF AMINO ACIDS
ARE ABOUT TO COMBINE
TO FORM
THE FIRST PROTEIN.
THE BUILDING BLOCKS...
( chuckling )
OF WHAT YOU CALL LIFE.
STRANGE, ISN'T IT?
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW,
YOUR ENTIRE CIVILIZATION,
IT ALL BEGINS RIGHT HERE
IN THIS LITTLE POND OF GOO.
APPROPRIATE SOMEHOW,
ISN'T IT?
TOO BAD YOU DIDN'T BRING
YOUR MICROSCOPE.
IT'S QUITE FASCINATING.
OH, LOOK.
THERE THEY GO.
THE AMINO ACIDS
ARE MOVING CLOSER.
AND CLOSER.
AW...
NOTHING HAPPENED.
SEE WHAT YOU'VE DONE?
ARE YOU SAYING
THAT I CAUSED THE ANOMALY...
AND THAT THE ANOMALY SOMEHOW
DISRUPTED THE BEGINNINGS OF LIFE
ON EARTH?
CONGRATULATIONS.
( dramatic theme playing )
LET'S CONCENTRATE
ON HOW THIS ANOMALY
WAS INITIALLY FORMED.
SPECULATION.
OUR TACHYON PULSE
HAS BEEN UNABLE TO COMPLETELY
PENETRATE THE ANOMALY.
IF WE HAD INFORMATION
ON THE CENTER OF THE PHENOMENON
WE MIGHT HAVE A BASIS
FOR SPECULATION.
IS THERE ANY WAY THAT WE CAN
SCAN THE INTERIOR?
I'VE TRIED EVERYTHING I KNOW.
THERE'S JUST
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
THERE'S NOTHING ONBOARD
THAT WILL DO THE JOB.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT COULD?
IN THEORY, A TOMOGRAPHIC
IMAGING SCANNER
CAPABLE OF MULTI-PHASIC
RESOLUTION
WOULD BE ABLE TO PENETRATE
THIS MUCH INTERFERENCE.
THE DAYSTROM INSTITUTE
HAS BEEN WORKING
ON SUCH A DEVICE,
BUT IT IS STILL
ONLY THEORETICAL.
DATA, DO WE HAVE A TOMOGRAPHIC
IMAGING SCANNER ONBOARD?
YES, SIR.
CAN YOU USE IT
TO SCAN THE INTERIOR
OF THE ANOMALY?
POSSIBLY... THERE IS
A GREAT DEAL OF INTERFERENCE
BUT I AM GETTING
SOME READINGS.
THIS IS VERY UNUSUAL.
WHAT IS IT?
IT APPEARS THAT
OUR TACHYON PULSE
IS CONVERGING WITH
TWO OTHER TACHYON PULSES
AT THE CENTER
OF THE ANOMALY.
THE TWO OTHER PULSES
HAVE THE EXACT SAME
AMPLITUDE MODULATION
AS OUR OWN PULSE.
IT IS AS IF ALL THREE
ORIGINATED FROM THE ENTERPRISE.
THREE PULSES...
FROM THREE TIME PERIODS
CONVERGING
AT ONE POINT IN SPACE.
Data:
CAPTAIN, WHAT ARE YOU
SUGGESTING?
COMPUTER,
WHERE IS ADMIRAL RIKER?
Computer:
Admiral Riker is in
Ten Forward.
THE SHIP HAS HELD UP
PRETTY WELL OVER THE YEARS.
THEY TRIED TO DE-COMMISSION HER
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO.
ONE OF THE ADVANTAGES
OF BEING AN ADMIRAL
IS YOU GET TO CHOOSE
YOUR OWN SHIP.
WILL, HOW LONG IS THIS THING
BETWEEN YOU AND WORF
GOING TO GO ON?
IT'S BEEN GOING ON
FOR OVER 20 YEARS.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
IT'S GOING TO END ANYTIME SOON.
I SUSPECT THE LAST THING
COUNSELOR TROI WOULD HAVE WANTED
IS FOR THE TWO OF YOU
TO BE ALIENATED.
I AGREE.
I THINK IT'S TIME
TO PUT IT BEHIND YOU.
I TRIED AT DEANNA'S FUNERAL.
HE WOULDN'T EVEN TALK WITH ME.
MIGHT HAVE BEEN TOUGH
FOR HIM THEN.
HE TOOK HER DEATH PRETTY HARD.
OH, YEAH?
WELL, HE WASN'T THE ONLY ONE.
I KNOW, BUT I THINK
IN HIS MIND,
YOU WERE THE REASON
THAT HE AND DEANNA
NEVER GOT TOGETHER.
I NEVER DID ANYTHING
TO STAND IN HIS WAY.
DIDN'T YOU, WILL?
DID I?
I DIDN'T WANT TO ADMIT
THAT IT WAS OVER.
I ALWAYS THOUGHT THAT WE
WOULD GET TOGETHER AGAIN
AND THEN SHE WAS GONE.
YOU THINK YOU HAVE ALL THE TIME
IN THE WORLD, UNTIL...
YEAH.
( dramatic theme playing )
ENSIGN, HOW DO I GET
TO TEN FORWARD?
IT'S FOUR DECKS DOWN, SIR--
SECTION 005.
THANK YOU.
( indistinct chattering )
OH, MY GOD.
WILL. WILL, I KNOW
WHY IT'S HAPPENING.
I KNOW WHAT'S CAUSING
THE ANOMALY.
WE HAVE TO GO BACK.
THE ONLY PLACE WE'RE GOING
BACK TO, SIR, IS BED.
DAMN IT, WILL,
I KNOW WHY IT'S HAPPENING!
WE CAUSED THE ANOMALY
WITH THE TACHYON PULSE.
IT HAPPENED
THREE TIMES, WILL.
WE DID IT IN THREE
DIFFERENT TIME PERIODS.
I THINK
YOU BETTER COME WITH ME.
WILL YOU LEAVE ME ALONE?
DAMN IT, I'M NOT STUPID!
WILL, THE TACHYON PULSES--
THEY WERE USED
IN THE SAME SPOT IN THREE
DIFFERENT TIME PERIODS.
DON'T YOU SEE?
WHEN THE TACHYON PULSE USED...
I MEAN, UH...
I MEAN,
WHEN THE PASTEUR
USED THE TACHYON PULSE,
THEN, THEN...
WE, UH...
I MEAN,
EVERYTHING STARTED, WILL.
WE SET EVERYTHING
IN MOTION.
IT... IT'S LIKE THE CHICKEN
AND THE EGG, WILL--
THE CHICKEN AND THE EGG!
WE THINK IT STARTED
IN THE PAST, BUT IT DIDN'T.
IT STARTED RIGHT HERE
IN THE FUTURE.
THAT'S WHY IT'S GETTING LARGER
IN THE PAST.
I KNOW WHAT THE CAPTAIN
IS TALKING ABOUT.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN,
HE'S DESCRIBING A PARADOX.
YES! RIGHT, THAT'S IT.
INTRIGUING.
IT IS POSSIBLE.
WE COULD HAVE CAUSED
THE VERY ANOMALY
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR.
LET US ASSUME
FOR A MOMENT
THAT THE CAPTAIN HAS BEEN
TRAVELING THROUGH TIME.
LET US ALSO ASSUME
HE HAS INITIATED A TACHYON PULSE
AT THE SAME COORDINATES
IN ALL THREE TIME PERIODS.
IN THAT CASE, IT IS POSSIBLE
THAT THE CONVERGENCE
OF THREE TACHYON PULSES
COULD HAVE RUPTURED
THE SUBSPACE BARRIER
AND CREATED
AN ANTI-TIME REACTION.
I SEE WHERE YOU'RE GOING, DATA.
AND BECAUSE ANTI-TIME
OPERATES OPPOSITE
THE WAY NORMAL TIME DOES
THE EFFECTS
WOULD TRAVEL BACKWARDS
THROUGH THE SPACE-TIME
CONTINUUM.
YES, THAT'S WHY IT GETS LARGER
IN THE PAST.
IT GROWS AS IT TRAVELS
BACKWARDS IN TIME.
ALL RIGHT, JUST FOR THE MOMENT,
LET'S SAY THAT YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHAT DO WE DO?
BACK, WILL.
WE GO BACK
TO THE DEVRON SYSTEM.
HE MAY BE RIGHT.
IF WE GO BACK
TO THE DEVRON SYSTEM NOW
WE MIGHT
BE ABLE TO SEE
THE INITIAL FORMATION
OF THE ANOMALY.
RIKER TO BRIDGE.
SET A COURSE FOR
THE DEVRON SYSTEM, MAXIMUM WARP.
Aye, sir.
WORF, WE COULD USE A HAND.
( dramatic theme playing )
ENTERING
THE DEVRON SYSTEM, SIR.
FULL STOP.
Data:
SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
A SMALL TEMPORAL ANOMALY
OFF THE PORT BOW.
ON SCREEN.
I WAS RIGHT.
La Forge:
IT'S AN ANTI-TIME ERUPTION
IT SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN FORMED
WITHIN THE LAST SIX HOURS.
WE MUST STOP IT HERE
SO THAT IT CAN'T TRAVEL
BACK THROUGH TIME.
Riker:
MR. DATA, WE NEED A SOLUTION
AND WE NEED IT NOW.
THE ANOMALY
IS BEING SUSTAINED
BY THE CONTINUING
TACHYON PULSES
FROM THE OTHER
TWO TIME PERIODS.
I SUGGEST
SHUTTING THEM DOWN.
THE NEXT TIME I'M THERE,
IT'S THE FIRST THING I'LL DO.
ISN'T THERE SOMETHING MORE
WE CAN DO HERE?
SEAL THE RUPTURE SOMEHOW?
I'LL INVESTIGATE
THE OPTIONS.
DATA, DISENGAGE
THE TACHYON PULSE.
SIR?
DO IT. THE CONVERGENCE
OF THE TACHYON PULSES
FROM THE THREE TIME PERIODS
IS WHAT IS CAUSING
THE ANOMALY.
AYE, SIR.
IS THERE ANY CHANGE
IN THE ANOMALY?
NO, SIR.
DISENGAGE THE TACHYON PULSE.
BUT WE HAVEN'T FINISHED
THE SCAN, SIR.
I KNOW THAT.
BUT IT IS IMPERATIVE
THAT YOU DISENGAGE
THE TACHYON PULSE IMMEDIATELY.
Data:
AYE, SIR. DISENGAGING.
WHY ISN'T THE ANOMALY
BEING AFFECTED?
WHY WOULD IT BE, SIR?
I'VE SHUT OFF THE TACHYON PULSES
IN THE OTHER TIME PERIODS.
BUT IT HASN'T CHANGED
THE ANOMALY.
IT REMAINS UNAFFECTED
HERE AS WELL, SIR.
WHAT DO WE DO?
THE ONLY WAY TO STOP THIS THING
IS TO REPAIR THE RUPTURE
AT THE FOCAL POINT
WHERE TIME AND ANTI-TIME
ARE CONVERGING.
HOW DO WE DO THAT?
IT WOULD REQUIRE TAKING THE SHIP
INTO THE ANOMALY ITSELF.
ONCE INSIDE, WE MAY BE ABLE
TO USE OUR ENGINES
TO CREATE
A STATIC WARP SHELL.
YEAH, DATA, THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THE SHELL WOULD ACT
AS AN ARTIFICIAL
SUBSPACE BARRIER
SEPARATING TIME
AND ANTI-TIME.
COLLAPSING THE ANOMALY
AND RESTORING
THE NORMAL FLOW OF TIME.
BUT THIS WOULD HAVE
TO BE DONE
IN THE OTHER
TWO TIME PERIODS, AS WELL.
THAT COULD BE A PROBLEM.
THE ANOMALY IS SO MUCH LARGER
IN THE OTHER TWO TIME PERIODS
IT MAY BE DANGEROUS
TO TAKE THE SHIP IN.
TAKE THE SHIP
IN WHERE, SIR?
INTO THE ANOMALY, CHIEF.
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR THE EXACT CENTER
AND TRANSFER ALL AVAILABLE POWER
TO THE SHIELDS.
SIR, CAN YOU GIVE US
SOME EXPLANATION?
NO, LIEUTENANT, I CANNOT.
CAPTAIN, SO FAR,
WE'VE OBEYED EVERY ORDER
NO MATTER HOW FARFETCHED
IT MIGHT HAVE SEEMED.
BUT IF WE'RE TO RISK
THE SAFETY
OF THE SHIP AND CREW,
I THINK WE HAVE TO ASK YOU
FOR AN EXPLANATION.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR CONCERNS,
LIEUTENANT
AND I KNOW
THAT IF I WERE IN YOUR POSITION
I WOULD BE DOING
THE SAME THING:
LOOKING FOR ANSWERS.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO FIND ANY,
BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE ANY
TO GIVE YOU.
I KNOW IT IS DIFFICULT
FOR YOU TO UNDERSTAND,
BUT WE HAVE TO TAKE THE SHIP
INTO THE VERY CENTER
OF THE PHENOMENON
AND CREATE
A STATIC WARP SHELL.
NOW, THIS WILL PUT
THE SHIP AT RISK.
QUITE FRANKLY,
WE MAY NOT SURVIVE.
BUT I WANT YOU TO BELIEVE
THAT I'M DOING THIS
FOR A GREATER PURPOSE,
AND THAT WHAT IS AT STAKE HERE
IS MORE THAN ANY OF YOU
CAN POSSIBLY IMAGINE.
I KNOW YOU HAVE YOUR DOUBTS
ABOUT ME.
ABOUT EACH OTHER.
ABOUT THE SHIP.
ALL I CAN SAY IS THAT
ALTHOUGH WE HAVE ONLY
BEEN TOGETHER FOR A SHORT TIME,
I KNOW THAT YOU ARE
THE FINEST CREW IN THE FLEET.
AND I WOULD TRUST EACH OF YOU
WITH MY LIFE.
SO I'M ASKING YOU
FOR A LEAP OF FAITH...
AND TO TRUST ME.
SHIELDS UP, MAXIMUM STRENGTH.
BOOSTING FIELD INTEGRITY
TO THE WARP NACELLES.
WE MAY ENCOUNTER
SHEARING FORCES
ONCE WE ENTER
THE ANOMALY.
I AM PREPARING TO INITIATE
A STATIC WARP SHELL.
COURSE LAID IN, SIR.
ALL DECKS REPORT READY, SIR.
TAKE US IN, CHIEF.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE AN IDEA.
IF WE TAKE THE SHIP
TO THE CENTER OF THE ANOMALY...
Both:
AND CREATE A STATIC WARP SHELL
YOU COULD REPAIR THE BARRIER
AND COLLAPSE THE ANOMALY.
YES, SIR.
MR. DATA,
YOU ARE A CLEVER MAN...
IN ANY TIME PERIOD.
HELM, LAY IN A COURSE
FOR THE CENTER OF THE ANOMALY.
AND PREPARE TO INITIATE
A STATIC WARP SHELL.
Helm:
AYE, SIR.
THE OTHER TWO ENTERPRISES--
THEY'RE ON THEIR WAY.
VERY WELL.
ENSIGN, TAKE US IN.
( dramatic theme playing )
WE'RE ENTERING THE ANOMALY, SIR.
ALL HANDS
BRACE FOR IMPACT.
Yar:
THE TEMPORAL ENERGY
IS INTERFERING WITH MAIN POWER.
SWITCHING TO--
AUXILIARY POWER!
I'M HAVING TROUBLE KEEPING
THE IMPULSE ENGINES ONLINE.
I'VE GOT POWER FLUCTUATIONS ALL
ACROSS THE BOARD.
MAINTAIN COURSE
AND SPEED.
MR. DATA, HOW LONG
UNTIL WE REACH THE CENTER?
AT LEAST 30 SECONDS, SIR.
( majestic theme playing )
WE'VE ENTERED THE ANOMALY.
WE HAVE REACHED THE CENTER, SIR.
INITIATE WARP SHELL.
INITIATING
STATIC WARP SHELL NOW.
IS IT HAVING ANY EFFECT?
SOMETHING IS HAPPENING.
A NEW SUBSPACE BARRIER
APPEARS TO BE FORMING.
CAPTAIN, THE SENSORS
ARE PICKING UP TWO OTHER SHIPS.
( suspenseful theme playing )
CAPTAIN, IT APPEARS
TO BE WORKING.
THE ANOMALY IS BEGINNING
TO COLLAPSE. I THINK--
THE TEMPORAL ENERGY IS RUPTURING
OUR WARP CONTAINMENT SYSTEM.
WE MUST EJECT THE CORE.
NO. WE HAVE TO MAINTAIN
THE STATIC WARP SHELL
AS LONG AS POSSIBLE.
WE'RE LOSING CONTAINMENT,
CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T STOP IT.
IT'S GOING TO...
Picard:
TRANSFER EMERGENCY POWER
TO THE ANTI-MATTER
CONTAINMENT SYSTEM.
I'M TRYING, BUT THERE'S A LOT
OF INTERFERENCE.
THE WARP SHELL IS DEFINITELY
HAVING AN EFFECT, SIR.
THE ANOMALY IS COLLAPSING.
I CAN'T HOLD IT.
THE CONTAINMENT SYSTEM IS GOING.
MAINTAIN YOUR POSITION.
MR. La FORGE...
BOTH OF THE OTHER SHIPS
HAVE BEEN DESTROYED.
TWO DOWN, ONE TO GO.
DATA, REPORT.
THE ANOMALY IS NEARLY COLLAPSED.
WE'RE LOSING CONTAINMENT.
GOOD-BYE, JEAN-LUC.
I'M GOING TO MISS YOU.
YOU HAD SUCH POTENTIAL.
BUT THEN AGAIN ALL GOOD THINGS
MUST COME TO AN END.
CONTAINMENT FIELD
IS AT CRITICAL!
I'M LOSING IT!
THE CONTINUUM DIDN'T THINK
YOU HAD IT IN YOU, JEAN-LUC,
BUT I KNEW YOU DID.
ARE YOU SAYING THAT IT WORKED?
WE COLLAPSED THE ANOMALY?
IS THAT ALL
THIS MEANT TO YOU?
JUST ANOTHER
SPATIAL ANOMALY?
JUST ANOTHER DAY
AT THE OFFICE?
DID IT WORK?
WELL YOU'RE HERE, AREN'T YOU?
YOU'RE TALKING TO ME,
AREN'T YOU?
WHAT ABOUT MY CREW?
( scoffs )
THE ANOMALY...
MY SHIP... MY CREW--
I SUPPOSE YOU'RE WORRIED
ABOUT YOUR FISH TOO.
IF IT PUTS YOUR MIND AT EASE,
YOU'VE SAVED HUMANITY...
ONCE AGAIN.
THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT?
YOU HAD A HAND
IN HELPING ME GET OUT OF THIS.
I WAS THE ONE
THAT GOT YOU INTO IT--
A DIRECTIVE FROM THE CONTINUUM.
THE PART ABOUT
THE HELPING HAND, THOUGH...
WAS MY IDEA.
I SINCERELY HOPE
THAT THIS IS THE LAST TIME
THAT I FIND MYSELF HERE.
YOU JUST DON'T GET IT,
DO YOU, JEAN-LUC?
THE TRIAL NEVER ENDS.
WE WANTED TO SEE
IF YOU HAD THE ABILITY
TO EXPAND YOUR MIND
AND YOUR HORIZONS.
AND FOR ONE BRIEF MOMENT,
YOU DID.
WHEN I REALIZED
THE PARADOX.
EXACTLY.
FOR THAT ONE FRACTION
OF A SECOND
YOU WERE OPEN TO OPTIONS
YOU HAD NEVER CONSIDERED.
THAT IS THE EXPLORATION
THAT AWAITS YOU.
NOT MAPPING STARS
AND STUDYING NEBULAE,
BUT CHARTING THE UNKNOWN
POSSIBILITIES OF EXISTENCE.
Q, WHAT IS IT
THAT YOU'RE TRYING TO TELL ME?
YOU'LL FIND OUT.
IN ANY CASE,
I'LL BE WATCHING.
AND IF YOU'RE VERY LUCKY
I'LL DROP BY TO SAY HELLO
FROM TIME TO TIME.
SEE YOU... OUT THERE.
( dramatic theme playing )
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
MR. WORF,
WHAT'S THE DATE?
STARDATE 47988.
( inhales and exhales deeply )
IS SOMETHING WRONG,
SIR?
NO. NO.
NO, UH...
I, UH, I THINK
I'LL GET BACK TO BED.
I...
I COULD USE SOME SLEEP.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
STARFLEET COMMAND REPORTS
NO UNUSUAL ACTIVITY
ALONG THE NEUTRAL ZONE
AND THERE IS NO SIGN
OF THE TEMPORAL ANOMALY.
IT WOULD APPEAR THAT I AM
THE ONLY MEMBER OF THE CREW
TO RETAIN ANY KNOWLEDGE
OF THE EVENTS I EXPERIENCED.
TAKE IT.
ANY TIME, DOCTOR.
Worf:
FOUR HANDS IN A ROW.
HOW DOES HE DO IT?
I CHEAT.
I'M KIDDING.
YOU KNOW,
I WAS THINKING
ABOUT WHAT
THE CAPTAIN TOLD US
ALL ABOUT THE FUTURE,
ABOUT HOW WE ALL CHANGED
AND DRIFTED APART.
WHY WOULD HE WANT TO TELL US
WHAT'S TO COME?
IT SURE GOES AGAINST EVERYTHING
WE'VE ALWAYS HEARD
ABOUT NOT POLLUTING
THE TIMELINE, DOESN'T IT?
I BELIEVE, HOWEVER,
THIS SITUATION IS UNIQUE.
SINCE THE ANOMALY DID NOT OCCUR,
THERE HAVE ALREADY BEEN CHANGES
IN THE WAY
THIS TIMELINE IS UNFOLDING.
THE FUTURE WE EXPERIENCE
WILL UNDOUBTEDLY BE DIFFERENT
FROM THE ONE
THE CAPTAIN ENCOUNTERED.
MAYBE THAT'S WHY HE TOLD US.
KNOWING WHAT HAPPENS
IN THAT FUTURE
ALLOWS US TO CHANGE THINGS NOW
SO THAT SOME THINGS
NEVER HAPPEN.
AGREED.
( door chimes )
Riker:
COME IN.
AM I TOO LATE?
OF COURSE NOT.
PULL UP A CHAIR.
Data:
FIVE CARD DRAW, DEUCES WILD.
( door chimes )
Riker:
COME IN.
IS THERE A PROBLEM, SIR?
NO. I, UH, I JUST THOUGHT
THAT I MIGHT, UM...
I MIGHT JOIN YOU
THIS EVENING...
IF THERE'S ROOM.
Riker:
OF COURSE.
HAVE A SEAT.
WOULD YOU CARE TO DEAL,
SIR?
OH, THANK YOU, MR. DATA.
ACTUALLY, I USED TO BE
QUITE A CARD PLAYER
IN MY YOUTH, YOU KNOW.
I SHOULD HAVE DONE THIS
A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU WERE ALWAYS WELCOME.
( poker chip
shuffles and clinks )
SO...
FIVE CARD STUD, NOTHING WILD...
AND THE SKY'S THE LIMIT.
( dramatic theme playing )
( adventurous theme playing )