WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
Katara:
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO
TELL ME STORIES ABOUT
THE OLD DAYS--
A TIME OF PEACE,
WHEN THE AVATAR KEPT BALANCE
BETWEEN WATER TRIBES,
EARTH KINGDOM,
FIRE NATION,
AND AIR NOMADS.
BUT THAT ALL CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR MASTERED
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS.
ONLY HE COULD STOP
THE RUTHLESS FIREBENDERS.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS
HAVE PASSED,
AND THE FIRE NATION
IS NEARING VICTORY
IN THE WAR.
TWO YEARS AGO,
MY FATHER AND
THE MEN OF MY TRIBE
JOURNEYED TO
THE EARTH KINGDOM
TO HELP FIGHT AGAINST
THE FIRE NATION,
LEAVING ME AND MY BROTHER
TO LOOK AFTER OUR TRIBE.
SOME PEOPLE BELIEVE
THAT THE AVATAR
WAS NEVER REBORN
INTO THE AIR NOMADS,
AND THAT THE CYCLE
IS BROKEN.
BUT I HAVEN'T
LOST HOPE.
I STILL BELIEVE
THAT SOMEHOW
THE AVATAR WILL RETURN
TO SAVE THE WORLD.
IT'S NOT GETTING AWAY
FROM ME THIS TIME.
WATCH AND LEARN,
KATARA.
THIS IS HOW
YOU CATCH A FISH.
SOKKA, LOOK!
SHH, KATARA.
YOU'RE GONNA
SCARE IT AWAY.
MMM. I CAN ALREADY
SMELL IT COOKING.
BUT, SOKKA,
I CAUGHT ONE.
HEY!
AAH!
WHY IS IT
THAT EVERY TIME
YOU PLAY WITH
MAGIC WATER,
I GET SOAKED?
OHH. IT'S NOT MAGIC.
IT'S WATERBENDING.
AND IT'S--
YEAH, YEAH--AN ANCIENT ART
UNIQUE TO OUR CULTURE,
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH...
LOOK, I'M JUST SAYING
THAT IF I HAD WEIRD POWERS,
I'D KEEP MY WEIRDNESS
TO MYSELF.
YOU'RE CALLING ME WEIRD?
I'M NOT THE ONE WHO MAKES
MUSCLES AT MYSELF
EVERY TIME I SEE
MY REFLECTION
IN THE WATER.
AAH!
[CRASH]
[MOANING]
WATCH OUT!
AAH!
GO LEFT!
YOU CALL THAT
LEFT?
YOU DON'T LIKE
MY STEERING.
WELL, MAYBE
YOU SHOULD HAVE
WATERBENDED US
OUT OF THE ICE.
SO IT'S MY FAULT.
I KNEW I SHOULD HAVE
LEFT YOU HOME.
LEAVE IT TO A GIRL
TO SCREW THINGS UP.
YOU ARE THE MOST
SEXIST, IMMATURE,
NUTBRAINED--
AH! I'M EMBARRASSED
TO BE RELATED TO YOU!
[CRACK]
EVER SINCE MOM DIED,
I'VE BEEN DOING ALL
THE WORK AROUND CAMP,
WHILE YOU'VE BEEN OFF
PLAYING SOLDIER.
AH...KATARA...
I EVEN WASH
ALL THE CLOTHES.
HAVE YOU EVER SMELLED
YOUR DIRTY SOCKS?
LET ME TELL YOU.
NOT PLEASANT!
KATARA! SETTLE DOWN!
NO! THAT'S IT.
I'M DONE HELPING YOU.
FROM NOW ON,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN!
[CRACK]
OH!
AAH!
[LOUD SPLASH]
OK. YOU'VE GONE
FROM WEIRD TO
FREAKISH, KATARA.
YOU MEAN,
I DID THAT?
YEP.
CONGRATULATIONS.
OH!
AH!
UH!
HE'S ALIVE.
WE HAVE TO HELP.
KATARA!
GET BACK HERE!
WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT THING IS.
UH!
UH! UH!
AAH!
[ROARING]
FINALLY.
UNCLE, DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT THIS MEANS?
I WON'T GET TO
FINISH MY GAME?
IT MEANS MY SEARCH
IS ABOUT TO
COME TO AN END.
AHH...
THAT LIGHT CAME FROM
AN INCREDIBLY
POWERFUL SOURCE.
IT HAS TO BE HIM.
OR IT'S JUST
THE CELESTIAL LIGHTS.
WE'VE BEEN DOWN
THIS ROAD BEFORE,
PRINCE ZUKO.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET TOO EXCITED
OVER NOTHING.
PLEASE, SIT.
WHY DON'T YOU ENJOY
A CUP OF CALMING
JASMINE TEA?
I DON'T NEED
ANY CALMING TEA!
I NEED TO CAPTURE
THE AVATAR!
HELMSMEN, HEAD A COURSE
FOR THE LIGHT.
[WIND BLOWING]
STOP!
AH!
UH!
STOP IT!
MMM...
AH!
I NEED TO
ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHAT?
PLEASE,
COME CLOSER.
WHAT IS IT?
WILL YOU GO
PENGUIN-SLEDDING WITH ME?
AH...SURE!
I GUESS.
UH!
WHAT'S
GOING ON HERE?
YOU TELL US!
HOW DID YOU
GET IN THE ICE?
AND WHY AREN'T
YOU FROZEN?
I'M NOT SURE.
[GROWLING]
AH! UH!
UH!
[GROWLING]
AH!
APPA, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
WAKE UP, BUDDY.
UNH! UNH!
AAH!
UNH!
HA HA!
YOU'RE OK.
WHAT IS
THAT THING?
THIS IS APPA,
MY FLYING BISON.
RIGHT.
AND THIS IS KATARA,
MY FLYING SISTER.
GRRR.
LOOK OUT!
OH! UGH! UGH!
AGH! AGH!
DON'T WORRY.
IT'LL WASH OUT.
AGH!
SO, DO YOU GUYS
LIVE AROUND HERE?
DON'T ANSWER
THAT.
DID YOU SEE
THAT CRAZY
BOLT OF LIGHT?
HE WAS PROBABLY
TRYING TO SIGNAL
THE FIRE NAVY.
OH, YEAH. I'M SURE
HE'S A SPY FOR THE FIRE NAVY.
YOU CAN TELL BY
THAT EVIL LOOK IN HIS EYE.
THE PARANOID ONE
IS MY BROTHER SOKKA.
YOU NEVER TOLD US
YOUR NAME.
I'M--AH! AH!
AH! AH! AH!
AH-CHOO!
[WIND BLOWING]
I'M AANG.
YOU JUST
SNEEZED
AND FLEW
10 FEET
IN THE AIR.
REALLY? IT FELT
HIGHER THAN THAT.
OH! YOU'RE
AN AIRBENDER.
SURE AM.
GIANT
LIGHT BEAMS,
FLYING BISON,
AIRBENDERS--
I THINK I GOT
MIDNIGHT SUN
MADNESS.
I'M GOING HOME TO
WHERE STUFF MAKES SENSE.
WELL, IF YOU GUYS
ARE STUCK,
APPA AND I CAN GIVE
YOU A LIFT.
WE'D LOVE A RIDE.
THANKS.
OH, NO!
I AM NOT GETTING
ON THAT FLUFFY
SNOT MONSTER.
ARE YOU HOPING
SOME OTHER
KIND OF MONSTER
WILL COME ALONG
AND GIVE YOU
A RIDE HOME?
YOU KNOW, BEFORE
YOU FREEZE TO DEATH.
AH--
[SIGHS]
OK. FIRST-TIME FLYERS,
HOLD ON TIGHT.
APPA, YIP YIP.
Appa: GRR.
Aang: COME ON, APPA,
YIP YIP.
WOW, THAT WAS
TRULY AMAZING.
APPA'S JUST TIRED.
A LITTLE REST
AND HE'LL BE SOARING
THROUGH THE SKY.
YOU'LL SEE.
WHY ARE YOU SMILING
AT ME LIKE THAT?
OH. I WAS SMILING?
ARGH!
I'M GOING
TO BED NOW.
[YAWN]
YEP. A MAN
NEEDS HIS REST.
PRINCE ZUKO,
YOU NEED SOME SLEEP.
EVEN IF YOU'RE RIGHT
AND THE AVATAR IS ALIVE,
YOU WON'T FIND HIM.
YOUR FATHER, GRANDFATHER,
AND GREAT-GRANDFATHER
ALL TRIED AND FAILED.
BECAUSE THEIR HONOR DIDN'T HINGE
ON THE AVATAR'S CAPTURE.
MINE DOES.
THIS COWARD'S HUNDRED YEARS
IN HIDING ARE OVER.
HEY.
HEY. WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT?
I GUESS I WAS WONDERING.
YOUR BEING
AN AIRBENDER AND ALL...
IF YOU HAD ANY IDEA
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE AVATAR.
UH...NO.
I DIDN'T KNOW HIM.
I MEAN, I KNEW PEOPLE
THAT KNEW HIM.
BUT I DIDN'T.
SORRY.
OK. JUST CURIOUS.
GOOD NIGHT.
SLEEP TIGHT.
[THUNDER AND LIGHTNING]
AHH!
AAH!
[ROAR]
Katara: AANG.
AANG, WAKE UP!
AH!
IT'S OK.
WE'RE IN
THE VILLAGE NOW.
COME ON, GET READY.
EVERYONE'S WAITING
TO MEET YOU.
OH!
AAH!
AANG, THIS IS
THE ENTIRE VILLAGE.
ENTIRE VILLAGE,
AANG.
UH...
WHY ARE THEY ALL
LOOKING AT ME
LIKE THAT?
DID APPA
SNEEZE ON ME?
WELL, NO ONE
HAS SEEN
AN AIRBENDER
IN A HUNDRED YEARS.
WE THOUGHT
THEY WERE EXTINCT.
UNTIL MY GRANDDAUGHTER
AND GRANDSON
FOUND YOU.
EXTINCT?
AANG, THIS IS
MY GRANDMOTHER.
CALL ME GRAN GRAN.
WHAT IS THIS,
A WEAPON?
YOU CAN'T STAB
ANYTHING WITH THIS.
IT'S NOT FOR STABBING.
IT'S FOR AIRBENDING.
AH!
MAGIC TRICK,
DO IT AGAIN.
NOT MAGIC,
AIRBENDING.
IT LETS ME CONTROL
THE AIR CURRENTS AROUND
MY GLIDER AND FLY.
YOU KNOW,
LAST TIME I CHECKED,
HUMANS CAN'T FLY.
CHECK AGAIN!
AH!
WOW, HE'S FLYING.
HE'S AMAZING!
UNH!
UH! UH!
OH! MY WATCHTOWER.
THAT WAS AMAZING.
UH!
GREAT.
YOU'RE AN AIRBENDER,
KATARA'S A WATERBENDER.
TOGETHER YOU CAN JUST
WASTE TIME ALL DAY LONG.
YOU'RE A WATERBENDER!
WELL, SORT OF.
NOT YET.
ALL RIGHT.
NO MORE PLAYING.
COME ON, KATARA.
YOU HAVE CHORES.
Katara: I TOLD YOU.
HE'S THE REAL THING, GRAN GRAN.
I FINALLY FOUND
A BENDER TO TEACH ME.
KATARA, TRY NOT TO
PUT ALL YOUR HOPES
IN THIS BOY.
BUT HE'S SPECIAL.
I CAN TELL.
I SENSE HE'S FILLED
WITH MUCH WISDOM.
SEE? NOW MY TONGUE IS
STUCK TO MY STAFF!
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
AGAIN.
AH! HIYA!
AHH. NO!
POWER AND FIREBENDING
COME FROM THE BREATH,
NOT THE MUSCLES.
THE BREATH BECOMES
ENERGY IN THE BODY.
THE ENERGY EXTENDS
PAST YOUR LIMBS
AND BECOMES FIRE!
GET IT RIGHT THIS TIME.
ENOUGH.
I'VE BEEN DRILLING
THIS SEQUENCE ALL DAY.
TEACH ME THE NEXT SET.
I'M MORE THAN READY.
NO! YOU'RE IMPATIENT.
YOU HAVE YET TO
MASTER YOUR BASICS.
DRILL IT AGAIN!
AHH! HIYA!
UH!
THE SAGES TELL US
THAT THE AVATAR IS
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
HE MUST BE OVER
A HUNDRED YEARS OLD
BY NOW.
HE'S HAD A CENTURY TO
MASTER THE 4 ELEMENTS.
I'LL NEED MORE THAN
BASIC FIREBENDING
TO DEFEAT HIM.
YOU WILL TEACH ME
THE ADVANCED SET!
VERY WELL.
BUT FIRST,
I MUST FINISH
MY ROAST DUCK.
YUM, YUM, YUM.
NOW, MEN, IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT YOU SHOW NO FEAR
WHEN YOU FACE A FIREBENDER.
IN THE WATER TRIBE, WE FIGHT
TILL THE LAST MAN'S STANDING.
FOR WITHOUT COURAGE,
HOW CAN WE CALL OURSELVES MEN?
I GOTTA PEE.
LISTEN! UNTIL YOUR FATHERS
RETURN FROM THE WAR,
THEY'RE COUNTING ON YOU
TO BE THE MEN OF THIS TRIBE.
AND THAT MEANS,
NO POTTY BREAKS.
BUT I REALLY GOTTA GO.
[SIGHS]
OK. WHO ELSE HAS TO GO?
UH!
HAVE YOU SEEN AANG?
GRAN GRAN SAID
HE DISAPPEARED
OVER AN HOUR AGO.
WOW! EVERYTHING FREEZES
IN THERE.
[LAUGHING]
AH! KATARA, GET HIM
OUT OF HERE.
THIS LESSON IS
FOR WARRIORS ONLY.
WEE!
HA! HA! HA!
[LAUGHING]
STOP! STOP IT
RIGHT NOW!
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR FUN AND GAMES
WITH A WAR GOING ON!
WHAT WAR?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YOU'RE KIDDING,
RIGHT?
PENGUIN!
OH!
HE'S KIDDING, RIGHT?
AANG!
HA! HA! HEY, COME ON,
LITTLE GUY.
WANNA GO SLEDDING?
UNH!
I HAVE A WAY
WITH ANIMALS.
YACK! YACK! YACK!
YACK! YACK!
HA HA HA!
AANG, I'LL HELP YOU
CATCH A PENGUIN
IF YOU TEACH ME
WATERBENDING.
YOU GOT A DEAL.
JUST ONE LITTLE PROBLEM.
I'M AN AIRBENDER,
NOT A WATERBENDER.
ISN'T THERE SOMEONE
IN YOUR TRIBE
WHO CAN TEACH YOU?
NO. YOU'RE LOOKING AT
THE ONLY WATERBENDER
IN THE WHOLE SOUTH POLE.
THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
A WATERBENDER
NEEDS TO MASTER WATER.
WHAT ABOUT THE NORTH POLE?
THERE'S ANOTHER WATER TRIBE
UP THERE, RIGHT?
MAYBE THEY HAVE
WATERBENDERS
WHO COULD TEACH YOU.
MAYBE, BUT WE
HAVEN'T HAD CONTACT
WITH OUR SISTER TRIBE
IN A LONG TIME.
IT'S NOT EXACTLY
TURN RIGHT AT
THE SECOND GLACIER.
IT'S ON THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE WORLD.
BUT YOU FORGET.
I HAVE A FLYING BISON.
APPA AND I CAN PERSONALLY
FLY YOU TO THE NORTH POLE.
KATARA, WE'RE GONNA
FIND YOU A MASTER.
THAT'S--I MEAN...
I DON'T KNOW.
I'VE NEVER LEFT HOME BEFORE.
WELL, YOU THINK
ABOUT IT.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME,
CAN YOU TEACH ME
TO CATCH ONE OF
THESE PENGUINS?
OK. LISTEN CLOSELY,
MY YOUNG PUPIL.
CATCHING PENGUINS IS
AN ANCIENT AND SACRED ART.
OBSERVE.
[SQUAWKING]
HA! HA! HA! HA!
AAH!
[LAUGHING]
HA! HA! YEAH!
HA! HA! HA! HA!
WHOO!
[LAUGHING]
I HAVEN'T DONE THIS
SINCE I WAS A KID.
YOU STILL ARE A KID.
[LAUGHING]
WHOA.
WHAT IS THAT?
A FIRE NAVY SHIP
AND A VERY BAD MEMORY
FOR MY PEOPLE.
AANG, STOP.
WE'RE NOT ALLOWED
TO GO NEAR IT.
THE SHIP COULD BE
BOOBY-TRAPPED.
IF YOU WANT
TO BE A BENDER,
YOU HAVE TO
LET GO OF FEAR.
THIS SHIP IS HAUNTED
BY TRIBES
SINCE GRAN GRAN
WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
IT WAS PART OF
THE FIRE NATION'S
FIRST ATTACKS.
OK. BACK UP.
I HAVE FRIENDS
ALL OVER THE WORLD,
EVEN IN THE FIRE NATION.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANY WAR.
AANG, HOW LONG
WERE YOU IN
THAT ICEBERG?
I DON'T KNOW.
A FEW DAYS MAYBE.
I THINK IT WAS MORE
LIKE A HUNDRED YEARS.
WHAT? THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
DO I LOOK LIKE
A 112-YEAR OLD MAN TO YOU?
THINK ABOUT IT.
THE WAR IS
A CENTURY OLD.
YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT
IT, BECAUSE SOMEHOW
YOU WERE IN THERE
THAT WHOLE TIME.
IT'S THE ONLY
EXPLANATION.
A HUNDRED YEARS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I'M SORRY, AANG.
MAYBE, SOMEHOW,
THERE'S
A BRIGHT SIDE
TO ALL THIS.
I DID GET TO MEET YOU.
COME ON. LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
AANG,
LET'S HEAD BACK.
THIS PLACE
IS CREEPY.
HUH?
WHAT'S THAT YOU SAID
ABOUT BOOBY TRAPS?
[GASPS]
AH!
UH-OH.
HOLD ON TIGHT!
AAH!
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
QUITE AGILE
FOR HIS OLD AGE.
WAKE MY UNCLE!
TELL HIM
I FOUND THE AVATAR.
AS WELL AS
HIS HIDING PLACE.
♪