Katara, voice-over:
WATER, EARTH,
FIRE, AIR...
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AND AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Katara:
HE'S ALIVE!
AAH!
FINALLY!
THAT LIGHT CAME FROM
AN INCREDIBLY POWERFUL SOURCE.
IT HAS TO BE HIM.
HEAD A COURSE FOR THE LIGHT.
I'M AANG.
YOU'RE AN AIRBENDER.
Katara: AANG, THIS IS
THE ENTIRE VILLAGE.
NO ONE HAS SEEN
AN AIRBENDER IN
A HUNDRED YEARS.
WE THOUGHT THEY
WERE EXTINCT.
EXTINCT?
YOU'RE LOOKING AT
THE ONLY WATERBENDER
IN THE WHOLE SOUTH POLE.
I HAVE A FLYING BISON.
APPA AND I CAN
PERSONALLY FLY YOU
TO THE NORTH POLE.
KATARA, WE'RE GONNA
FIND YOU A MASTER.
Aang: WHAT IS THAT?
Katara:
A FIRE NAVY SHIP.
AANG, STOP.
THE SHIP COULD BE
BOOBY TRAPPED.
AANG, HOW LONG WERE
YOU IN THAT ICEBERG?
I DON'T KNOW.
A FEW DAYS MAYBE.
Katara:
I THINK IT WAS MORE
LIKE A HUNDRED YEARS.
[BOTH GASP]
WHAT'S THAT YOU SAID
ABOUT BOOBY TRAPS?
UH-OH.
I FOUND THE AVATAR...
AS WELL AS HIS HIDING PLACE.
YAY!
AANG'S BACK!
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
I KNEW IT.
YOU SIGNALED
THE FIRE NAVY
WITH THAT FLARE.
YOU'RE LEADING THEM
STRAIGHT TO US,
AREN'T YOU?
AANG DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
YEAH, WE WERE
ON THE SHIP
AND THERE WAS
THIS BOOBY TRAP
AND, WELL, WE--
WE BOOBIED
RIGHT INTO IT.
KATARA,
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
GONE ON THAT SHIP.
NOW WE COULD ALL
BE IN DANGER.
DON'T BLAME KATARA.
I BROUGHT HER THERE.
IT'S MY FAULT.
A-HA!
THE TRAITOR
CONFESSES!
WARRIORS,
AWAY FROM THE ENEMY!
THE FOREIGNER
IS BANISHED
FROM OUR VILLAGE.
SOKKA,
YOU'RE MAKING
A MISTAKE.
NO, I'M KEEPING
MY PROMISE TO DAD.
I'M PROTECTING
YOU FROM THREATS
LIKE HIM.
AANG IS NOT
OUR ENEMY.
DON'T YOU SEE?
AANG'S BROUGHT
US SOMETHING
WE HAVEN'T HAD
IN A LONG TIME--FUN.
FUN? WE CAN'T
FIGHT FIREBENDERS
WITH FUN!
YOU SHOULD TRY IT
SOMETIME.
GET OUT OF
OUR VILLAGE NOW!
GRANDMOTHER, PLEASE,
DON'T LET SOKKA DO THIS.
KATARA, YOU KNEW
GOING ON THAT SHIP
WAS FORBIDDEN.
SOKKA IS RIGHT.
I THINK IT BEST
IF THE AIRBENDER
LEAVES.
FINE, THEN
I'M BANISHED, TOO.
COME ON, AANG,
LET'S GO.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
TO FIND A WATERBENDER.
AANG IS TAKING ME
TO THE NORTH POLE.
I AM?
GREAT!
KATARA, WOULD YOU
REALLY CHOOSE HIM
OVER YOUR TRIBE,
YOUR OWN FAMILY?
KATARA, I DON'T
WANT TO COME BETWEEN
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
SO YOU'RE LEAVING
THE SOUTH POLE?
THIS IS GOOD-BYE?
THANKS FOR
PENGUIN SLEDDING WITH ME.
WHERE WILL YOU GO?
GUESS I'LL GO BACK HOME
AND LOOK FOR THE AIRBENDERS.
WOW.
I HAVEN'T CLEANED MY ROOM
IN 100 YEARS.
NOT LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT.
IT WAS NICE
MEETING EVERYONE.
LET'S SEE YOUR BISON
FLY NOW, AIRBOY.
COME ON, APPA,
YOU CAN DO IT.
YIP YIP!
YEAH, I THOUGHT SO!
[CRYING]
AANG, DON'T GO.
I'LL MISS YOU.
I'LL MISS YOU, TOO.
COME ON, BOY.
[WHIMPERS]
KATARA, YOU'LL FEEL
BETTER AFTER YOU--
YOU HAPPY NOW?
THERE GOES MY ONE CHANCE
OF BECOMING A WATERBENDER!
ALL RIGHT,
READY OUR DEFENSES!
THE FIRE NATION
COULD BE ON OUR SHORES
ANY MOMENT NOW!
BUT I GOT TO--
AND NO POTTY BREAKS!
[YAWNS]
YEAH, I LIKED HER, TOO.
[GASPS]
THE VILLAGE!
APPA, WAIT HERE!
[EXPLOSION]
[GASPING]
[RUMBLING]
OH, MAN!
[WHIMPERING]
OH, MAN.
[VILLAGERS SCREAMING]
SOKKA! GET OUT
OF THE WAY!
[SHOUTING]
WHERE ARE YOU HIDING HIM?
HE'D BE ABOUT THIS AGE,
MASTER OF ALL ELEMENTS.
I KNOW YOU'RE HIDING HIM.
[SHOUTING]
SHOW NO FEAR!
[CHEERING]
HEY, KATARA.
HEY, SOKKA.
HI, AANG.
THANKS FOR
COMING.
LOOKING FOR ME?
YOU'RE THE AIRBENDER?
YOU'RE THE AVATAR?
AANG?
NO WAY.
I'VE SPENT YEARS PREPARING
FOR THIS ENCOUNTER,
TRAINING, MEDITATING.
YOU'RE JUST A CHILD.
WELL, YOU'RE JUST
A TEENAGER.
IF I GO WITH YOU,
WILL YOU PROMISE
TO LEAVE EVERYONE ALONE?
NO, AANG, DON'T DO THIS.
DON'T WORRY, KATARA.
IT'LL BE OK.
UNH!
TAKE CARE OF APPA FOR ME
UNTIL I GET BACK.
HEAD A COURSE
TO THE FIRE NATION.
I'M GOING HOME.
WE HAVE TO GO AFTER
THAT SHIP, SOKKA.
AANG SAVED OUR TRIBE.
NOW WE HAVE TO
SAVE HIM.
- KATARA, I--
- WHY CAN'T YOU REALIZE
THAT HE'S ON OUR SIDE?
IF WE DON'T HELP HIM,
NO ONE WILL.
I KNOW YOU DON'T LIKE AANG,
BUT WE OWE HIM AND--
KATARA, ARE YOU GOING
TO TALK ALL DAY
OR ARE YOU
COMING WITH ME?
SOKKA!
GET IN.
WE'RE GOING TO
SAVE YOUR BOYFRIEND.
HE'S NOT MY--
WHATEVER.
- WHAT DO YOU TWO
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
YOU'LL NEED THESE.
YOU HAVE A LONG JOURNEY
AHEAD OF YOU.
IT'S BEEN SO LONG
SINCE I'VE HAD HOPE,
BUT YOU BROUGHT IT
BACK TO LIFE,
MY LITTLE WATERBENDER.
AND YOU,
MY BRAVE WARRIOR,
BE NICE TO YOUR SISTER.
YEAH, OK, GRAN.
AANG IS THE AVATAR.
HE'S THE WORLD'S
ONLY CHANCE.
YOU BOTH FOUND HIM
FOR A REASON.
NOW YOUR DESTINIES
ARE INTERTWINED
WITH HIS.
THERE'S NO WAY
WE'RE GOING TO CATCH
A WARSHIP
WITH A CANOE.
[GRUMBLING]
APPA!
YOU JUST LOVE
TAKING ME OUT OF
MY COMFORT ZONE,
DON'T YOU?
THIS STAFF WILL MAKE
AN EXCELLENT GIFT
FOR MY FATHER.
I SUPPOSE
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
OF FATHERS,
BEING RAISED BY
MONKS.
TAKE THE AVATAR
TO THE PRISON HOLD
AND TAKE THIS
TO MY QUARTERS.
HEY, YOU MIND TAKING THIS
TO HIS QUARTERS FOR ME?
UGH!
SO, I GUESS YOU'VE NEVER
FOUGHT AN AIRBENDER BEFORE.
I BET I CAN TAKE YOU BOTH
WITH MY HANDS TIED
BEHIND MY BACK.
Man: SILENCE.
Man: THE AVATAR
HAS ESCAPED!
Sokka: GO.
FLY.
SOAR.
PLEASE, APPA,
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
AANG NEEDS YOUR HELP.
UP.
ASCEND.
ELEVATE.
SOKKA DOESN'T BELIEVE
YOU CAN FLY,
BUT I DO, APPA.
COME ON,
DON'T YOU WANT
TO SAVE AANG?
WHAT WAS IT
THAT KID SAID?
YEE-HA?
HUP-HUP?
WA-HOO?
UH, YIP YIP?
[APPA GROWLS]
Katara:
YOU DID IT, SOKKA!
HE'S FLYING!
KATARA, HE'S--
I MEAN, BIG DEAL.
HE'S FLYING.
AAH!
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN
MY STAFF AROUND, HAVE YOU?
THANKS, ANYWAY.
[MAN SNORING]
SORRY.
MY STAFF!
LOOKS LIKE I
UNDERESTIMATED YOU.
[APPA GROWLING]
WHAT IS THAT?
APPA!
AANG, NO!
AANG! AANG!
AANG!
DID YOU SEE
WHAT HE JUST DID?
NOW THAT WAS
SOME WATERBENDING.
Katara: AANG,
ARE YOU OK?
HEY, KATARA.
HEY, SOKKA.
THANKS FOR COMING.
WELL, I COULDN'T LET YOU
HAVE ALL THE GLORY.
I DROPPED MY STAFF.
GOT IT.
HA!
THAT'S FROM
THE WATER TRIBE!
KATARA!
[GRUNTING]
HURRY UP, SOKKA!
I'M JUST A GUY
WITH A BOOMERANG.
I DIDN'T ASK
FOR ALL THIS FLYING
AND MAGIC.
YIP YIP! YIP YIP!
HUH?
SHOOT THEM DOWN!
[LAUGHING]
GOOD NEWS
FOR THE FIRE LORD.
THE FIRE NATION'S
GREATEST THREAT
IS JUST
A LITTLE KID.
THAT KID, UNCLE,
JUST DID THIS.
I WON'T UNDERESTIMATE
HIM AGAIN.
DIG THIS SHIP OUT
AND FOLLOW THEM.
AS SOON AS
YOU'RE DONE WITH THAT.
Katara:
HOW DID YOU DO THAT
WITH THE WATER?
IT WAS THE MOST
AMAZING THING
I'VE EVER SEEN.
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST SORT OF DID IT.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
YOU WERE THE AVATAR?
BECAUSE I NEVER
WANTED TO BE.
BUT, AANG,
THE WORLD'S BEEN WAITING
FOR THE AVATAR TO RETURN
AND FINALLY PUT AN END
TO THIS WAR.
AND HOW AM I GOING TO
DO THAT?
ACCORDING TO LEGEND,
YOU NEED TO FIRST
MASTER WATER,
THEN EARTH,
THEN FIRE, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHAT
THE MONKS TOLD ME.
WELL, IF WE GO TO
THE NORTH POLE,
YOU CAN MASTER
WATERBENDING.
WE COULD LEARN IT
TOGETHER!
AND, SOKKA, I'M SURE
YOU'LL GET TO KNOCK
SOME FIREBENDER HEADS
ON THE WAY.
I'D LIKE THAT.
I'D REALLY LIKE THAT.
THEN WE'RE IN THIS
TOGETHER.
ALL RIGHT, BUT BEFORE
I LEARN WATERBENDING,
WE HAVE SOME SERIOUS
BUSINESS TO ATTEND TO
HERE, HERE, AND HERE.
WHAT'S THERE?
HERE WE'LL RIDE
THE HOPPING LLAMAS.
THEN WAY OVER HERE
WE'LL SURF ON THE BACKS
OF GIANT KOI FISH.
THEN BACK OVER HERE
WE'LL RIDE THE HOG MONKEYS.
THEY DON'T LIKE
PEOPLE RIDING THEM,
BUT THAT'S WHAT
MAKES IT FUN!
♪