Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG,
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
AANG, HOW LONG WERE
YOU IN THAT ICEBERG?
I DON'T KNOW.
A FEW DAYS MAYBE.
I THINK IT WAS MORE LIKE
A HUNDRED YEARS.
NO ONE HAS SEEN
AN AIRBENDER IN
A HUNDRED YEARS.
WE THOUGHT THEY
WERE EXTINCT.
ACCORDING TO LEGEND,
YOU NEED TO FIRST
MASTER WATER,
THEN EARTH,
THEN FIRE, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHAT
THE MONKS TOLD ME.
WELL, IF WE GO
TO THE NORTH POLE,
YOU CAN MASTER
WATERBENDING.
WAIT, MY UNCLE. TELL THEM I
FOUND THE AVATAR.
Aang: WAIT TILL
YOU SEE IT, KATARA.
THE AIR TEMPLE
IS ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL PLACES IN THE WORLD.
AANG, I KNOW
YOU'RE EXCITED,
BUT IT'S BEEN
A HUNDRED YEARS
SINCE YOU'VE BEEN HOME.
THAT'S WHY
I'M SO EXCITED!
IT'S JUST THAT
A LOT CAN CHANGE
IN ALL THAT TIME.
I KNOW,
BUT I NEED TO SEE IT
FOR MYSELF.
[SNORING]
WAKE UP, SOKKA.
AIR TEMPLE,
HERE WE COME!
[GROAN]
SLEEP NOW.
TEMPLE LATER.
[SNORING]
SOKKA, WAKE UP!
THERE'S
A PRICKLE SNAKE IN
YOUR SLEEPING BAG!
AAH!
GET IT OFF!
HEH HEH HEH!
GREAT.
YOU'RE AWAKE.
LET'S GO.
UNCLE, I WANT
THE REPAIRS MADE
AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
I DON'T WANT
TO STAY TOO LONG
AND RISK LOSING
HIS TRAIL.
YOU MEAN THE AVATAR?
DON'T MENTION
HIS NAME
ON THESE DOCKS.
ONCE WORD GETS OUT
THAT HE'S ALIVE,
EVERY FIREBENDER
WILL BE OUT
LOOKING FOR HIM,
- AND I DON'T WANT
ANYONE GETTING
IN THE WAY.
- GETTING IN THE WAY OF WHAT?
PRINCE ZUKO.
CAPTAIN ZHAO.
IT'S COMMANDER
NOW.
AND GENERAL IROH,
GREAT HERO
OF OUR NATION.
RETIRED GENERAL.
THE FIRE LORD'S
BROTHER AND SON
ARE WELCOME GUESTS
ANYTIME.
WHAT BRINGS YOU
TO MY HARBOR?
OUR SHIP
IS BEING REPAIRED.
THAT'S QUITE A BIT
OF DAMAGE.
YES. YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE WHAT HAPPENED.
UNCLE, TELL
COMMANDER ZHAO
WHAT HAPPENED.
YES, I WILL DO THAT.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
WHAT, DID WE CRASH
OR SOMETHING?
YES! RIGHT INTO
AN EARTH KINGDOM SHIP.
REALLY?
YOU MUST
REGALE ME WITH ALL
THE THRILLING DETAILS.
JOIN ME FOR A DRINK?
SORRY, BUT WE
HAVE TO GO.
PRINCE ZUKO,
SHOW COMMANDER ZHAO
YOUR RESPECT.
WE WOULD BE HONORED
TO JOIN YOU.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY GINSENG TEA?
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
[GRUNT]
[RUMBLES]
HEY, STOMACH,
BE QUIET, ALL RIGHT?
I'M TRYING TO
FIND US SOME FOOD.
HEY! WHO ATE ALL
MY BLUBBERED SEAL JERKY?
OH. THAT WAS FOOD?
I USED IT TO
START THE CAMPFIRE
LAST NIGHT.
SORRY.
YOU WHAT?
AWW.
NO WONDER THE FLAMES
SMELLED SO GOOD.
Aang: THE POTOLA
MOUNTAIN RANGE!
WE'RE ALMOST THERE!
AANG, BEFORE WE
GET TO THE TEMPLE,
I WANT TO
TALK TO YOU ABOUT
THE AIRBENDERS.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
WELL...
I JUST WANT YOU
TO BE PREPARED
FOR WHAT
YOU MIGHT SEE.
THE FIRE NATION
IS RUTHLESS.
THEY KILLED MY MOTHER,
AND THEY COULD HAVE
DONE THE SAME
TO YOUR PEOPLE.
JUST BECAUSE NO ONE
HAS SEEN AN AIRBENDER
DOESN'T MEAN
THE FIRE NATION
KILLED THEM ALL.
THEY PROBABLY ESCAPED.
I KNOW
IT'S HARD TO ACCEPT.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND,
KATARA.
THE ONLY WAY TO
GET TO AN AIRBENDER TEMPLE
IS ON A FLYING BISON,
AND I DOUBT
THE FIRE NATION
HAS ANY FLYING BISON.
RIGHT, APPA?
[APPA GROWLS]
YIP YIP!
Aang: THERE IT IS,
THE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
AANG, IT'S AMAZING!
WE'RE HOME, BUDDY.
WE'RE HOME.
AND BY YEAR'S END,
THE EARTH KINGDOM CAPITAL
WILL BE UNDER OUR RULE.
THE FIRE LORD WILL
FINALLY CLAIM VICTORY
IN THIS WAR.
IF MY FATHER THINKS
THE REST OF THE WORLD
WILL FOLLOW HIM
WILLINGLY,
THEN HE IS A FOOL.
TWO YEARS AT SEA
HAVE DONE LITTLE TO
TEMPER YOUR TONGUE.
SO, HOW'S YOUR SEARCH
FOR THE AVATAR GOING?
[CRASH]
UH... MY FAULT
ENTIRELY.
WE HAVEN'T
FOUND HIM YET.
DID YOU REALLY
EXPECT TO?
THE AVATAR DIED
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO
ALONG WITH THE REST
OF THE AIRBENDERS.
UNLESS YOU FOUND
SOME EVIDENCE
THAT THE AVATAR
IS ALIVE.
NO. NOTHING.
PRINCE ZUKO, THE AVATAR
IS THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN STOP
THE FIRE NATION
FROM WINNING
THIS WAR.
IF YOU HAVE AN OUNCE
OF LOYALTY LEFT,
YOU'LL TELL ME
WHAT YOU FOUND.
I HAVEN'T FOUND
ANYTHING.
IT'S LIKE YOU SAID--
THE AVATAR
PROBABLY DIED
A LONG TIME AGO.
COME ON, UNCLE.
WE'RE GOING.
Man: COMMANDER ZHAO,
WE INTERROGATED
THE CREW
AS YOU INSTRUCTED.
THEY CONFIRMED
PRINCE ZUKO
HAD THE AVATAR
IN CUSTODY
BUT LET HIM ESCAPE.
NOW REMIND ME,
HOW EXACTLY
WAS YOUR SHIP
DAMAGED?
SO WHERE DO I GET
SOMETHING TO EAT?
YOU'RE LUCKY ENOUGH
TO BE ONE OF
THE FIRST OUTSIDERS
TO EVER VISIT
AN AIRBENDER TEMPLE,
AND ALL YOU CAN
THINK ABOUT IS FOOD?
Sokka: I'M JUST A SIMPLE
GUY WITH SIMPLE NEEDS.
SO THAT'S WHERE
MY FRIENDS AND I
WOULD PLAY AIRBALL,
AND OVER THERE
IS WHERE THE BISON
WOULD SLEEP.
AND...
[SIGH]
WHAT'S WRONG?
THIS PLACE USED
TO BE FULL OF MONKS
AND LEMURS AND BISON.
NOW THERE'S JUST
A BUNCH OF WEEDS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW MUCH THINGS
HAVE CHANGED.
Sokka: SO, UH,
THIS AIRBALL GAME--
HOW DO YOU PLAY?
UGH!
OOH!
HA HA HA!
AANG 7, SOKKA 0.
MAKING HIM
FEEL BETTER
IS PUTTING ME
IN A WORLD OF HURT.
KATARA,
CHECK THIS OUT.
FIRE NATION.
WE SHOULD TELL HIM.
AANG, THERE'S SOMETHING
YOU NEED TO SEE.
OK.
OH!
WHAT IS IT?
UH...JUST A NEW
WATERBENDING MOVE
I LEARNED.
NICE ONE.
BUT ENOUGH PRACTICING.
WE HAVE
A WHOLE TEMPLE TO SEE.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T
PROTECT HIM FOREVER.
KATARA,
FIREBENDERS
WERE HERE.
YOU CAN'T PRETEND
THEY WEREN'T.
I CAN FOR AANG'S SAKE.
IF HE FINDS OUT
THAT THE FIRE NATION
INVADED HIS HOME,
HE'LL BE DEVASTATED.
Aang: HEY, GUYS!
I WANT YOU
TO MEET SOMEBODY.
WHO'S THAT?
MONK GYATSO,
THE GREATEST AIRBENDER
IN THE WORLD.
HE TAUGHT ME
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
BUT THE TRUE SECRET
IS IN THE GOOEY CENTER.
HMM.
MY ANCIENT
CAKE MAKING TECHNIQUE
ISN'T THE ONLY THING
ON YOUR MIND,
IS IT, AANG?
THIS WHOLE
AVATAR THING--
MAYBE THE MONKS
MADE A MISTAKE.
THE ONLY MISTAKE
THEY MADE
WAS TELLING YOU
BEFORE YOU TURNED 16.
BUT WE CAN'T
CONCERN OURSELVES
WITH WHAT WAS.
WE MUST ACT
ON WHAT IS.
BUT, GYATSO,
HOW DO I KNOW IF
I'M READY FOR THIS?
YOUR QUESTIONS
WILL BE ANSWERED
WHEN YOU'RE OLD ENOUGH
TO ENTER THE AIR TEMPLE
SANCTUARY.
INSIDE, YOU WILL
MEET SOMEONE
WHO WILL GUIDE YOU
ON YOUR JOURNEY.
WHO IS IT?
WHEN YOU ARE READY,
HE WILL REVEAL
HIMSELF TO YOU.
HMM.
NOW...
ARE YOU GOING
TO HELP ME
WITH THESE CAKES
OR NOT?
ALL RIGHT.
1...2...
3.
[LEMURS CHATTERING]
[LAUGHING]
YOUR AIM HAS
IMPROVED GREATLY,
MY YOUNG PUPIL.
YOU MUST MISS HIM.
YEAH.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
THE AIR TEMPLE SANCTUARY.
THERE'S SOMEONE
I'M READY TO MEET.
Katara: BUT, AANG,
NO ONE COULD HAVE
SURVIVED IN THERE
FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
IT'S NOT IMPOSSIBLE.
I SURVIVED
IN THE ICEBERG
FOR THAT LONG.
GOOD POINT.
KATARA,
WHOEVER'S IN THERE
MIGHT HELP ME
FIGURE OUT
THIS AVATAR THING.
AND WHOEVER'S IN THERE
MIGHT HAVE A MEDLEY
OF DELICIOUS
CURED MEATS.
OOH!
UNH!
OHH.
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU HAVE A KEY.
THE KEY, SOKKA,
IS AIRBENDING.
HELLO?
ANYONE HOME?
Zhao: SO A 12-YEAR-OLD BOY
BESTED YOU
AND YOUR FIREBENDERS.
YOU'RE MORE PATHETIC
THAN I THOUGHT.
I UNDERESTIMATED
HIM ONCE,
BUT IT WILL NOT
HAPPEN AGAIN.
NO, IT WILL NOT,
BECAUSE YOU WON'T
HAVE A SECOND CHANCE.
COMMANDER ZHAO, I'VE BEEN
HUNTING THE AVATAR FOR TWO
YEARS, AND I--
AND YOU FAILED.
CAPTURING THE AVATAR
IS TOO IMPORTANT
TO LEAVE
IN A TEENAGER'S HANDS.
HE'S MINE NOW.
[YELLS]
KEEP THEM HERE.
MORE TEA, PLEASE.
STATUES?
THAT'S IT?
WHERE'S THE MEAT?
WHO ARE
ALL THESE PEOPLE?
I'M NOT SURE.
BUT IT FEELS LIKE
I KNOW THEM SOMEHOW.
LOOK!
THAT ONE'S
AN AIRBENDER!
AND THIS ONE'S
A WATERBENDER.
THEY'RE LINED UP
IN A PATTERN.
AIR, WATER,
EARTH, AND FIRE.
THAT'S
THE AVATAR CYCLE.
OF COURSE.
THEY'RE AVATARS.
ALL THESE PEOPLE
ARE YOUR PAST
LIVES, AANG.
WOW!
THERE'S SO MANY.
PAST LIVES?
KATARA, YOU REALLY
BELIEVE IN THAT STUFF?
IT'S TRUE.
WHEN THE AVATAR
DIES,
HE'S REINCARNATED
INTO THE NEXT NATION
IN THE CYCLE.
Katara: AANG,
SNAP OUT OF IT.
HUH?
WHO IS THAT?
THAT'S AVATAR ROKU,
THE AVATAR BEFORE ME.
YOU WERE
A FIREBENDER?
NO WONDER
I DIDN'T TRUST YOU
WHEN WE FIRST MET.
THERE'S
NO WRITING.
HOW DO YOU
KNOW HIS NAME?
I'M NOT SURE.
I JUST KNOW IT
SOMEHOW.
[GRUNT]
YOU JUST COULDN'T
GET ANY WEIRDER.
♪♪
[WHISPERING]
FIREBENDER.
NOBODY MAKE A SOUND.
YOU'RE
MAKING A SOUND.
SHH!
THAT FIREBENDER
WON'T KNOW
WHAT HIT HIM.
[CHATTERING]
LEMUR!
DINNER.
DON'T LISTEN
TO HIM.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
MY NEW PET.
NOT IF I
GET HIM FIRST!
Aang: WAIT!
COME BACK!
Sokka:
I WANT TO EAT YOU!
HA HA HA!
AAH! UNH!
[LAUGHING]
HEY! NO FAIR!
MY SEARCH PARTY
IS READY.
ONCE I'M OUT TO SEA,
MY GUARDS WILL ESCORT YOU
BACK TO YOUR SHIP,
AND YOU WILL BE
FREE TO GO.
WHY? ARE YOU WORRIED
I'M GOING TO
TRY AND STOP YOU?
HA HA HA!
YOU...STOP ME?
IMPOSSIBLE.
DON'T UNDERESTIMATE
ME, ZHAO.
I WILL CAPTURE
THE AVATAR
BEFORE YOU.
PRINCE ZUKO,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU CAN'T
COMPETE WITH ME.
I HAVE HUNDREDS
OF WARSHIPS
UNDER MY COMMAND,
AND YOU,
YOU'RE JUST
A BANISHED PRINCE.
NO HOME, NO ALLIES.
YOUR OWN FATHER
DOESN'T EVEN WANT YOU.
YOU'RE WRONG.
ONCE I DELIVER THE AVATAR
TO MY FATHER,
HE WILL WELCOME ME HOME
WITH HONOR
AND RESTORE
MY RIGHTFUL PLACE
ON THE THRONE.
IF YOUR FATHER REALLY
WANTED YOU HOME,
HE WOULD HAVE LET YOU
RETURN BY NOW,
AVATAR OR NO AVATAR.
BUT IN HIS EYES,
YOU ARE A FAILURE
AND A DISGRACE
TO THE FIRE NATION.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
YOU HAVE THE SCAR
TO PROVE IT.
AAH! MAYBE YOU'D
LIKE ONE TO MATCH!
IS THAT A CHALLENGE?
AN AGNI KAI
AT SUNSET.
VERY WELL.
IT'S A SHAME
YOUR FATHER
WON'T BE HERE
TO WATCH ME
HUMILIATE YOU.
I GUESS
YOUR UNCLE WILL DO.
PRINCE ZUKO,
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
WHAT HAPPENED
THE LAST TIME
YOU DUELED A MASTER?
I WILL NEVER FORGET.
[CHATTERING]
HEY! COME BACK!
COME ON OUT,
LITTLE LEMUR.
THAT HUNGRY GUY
WON'T BOTHER YOU ANYMORE.
FIREBENDERS?
THEY WERE HERE?
GYATSO.
HEY, AANG,
YOU FIND MY DINNER YET?
[SOBBING]
AANG, I WASN'T
REALLY GONNA
EAT THE LEMUR, OK?
OH, MAN.
COME ON, AANG.
EVERYTHING
WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
[GASP]
AANG!
SEND WORD
TO THE FIRE LORD
IMMEDIATELY.
THE AVATAR
HAS RETURNED.
Sokka:
AANG, COME ON!
SNAP OUT OF IT! AAH!
AAH! UNH!
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE FOUND OUT
FIREBENDERS
KILLED GYATSO.
OH, NO.
IT'S HIS AVATAR
SPIRIT.
HE MUST HAVE
TRIGGERED IT.
I'M GONNA TRY
AND CALM HIM DOWN.
WELL, DO IT,
BEFORE HE BLOWS US
OFF THE MOUNTAIN!
REMEMBER YOUR
FIREBENDING BASICS,
PRINCE ZUKO.
THEY ARE
YOUR GREATEST
WEAPONS.
I REFUSE
TO LET HIM WIN.
THIS WILL BE OVER QUICKLY.
[YELLS]
[PANTING]
[YELLING]
BASICS, ZUKO.
BREAK HIS ROOT.
UNH!
[GROAN]
[YELLING]
AAH!
UNH!
DO IT!
THAT'S IT?
YOUR FATHER
RAISED A COWARD.
NEXT TIME YOU
GET IN MY WAY,
I PROMISE,
I WON'T HOLD BACK.
[YELLING]
UNH!
NO, PRINCE ZUKO.
DO NOT TAINT
YOUR VICTORY.
SO THIS IS HOW
THE GREAT
COMMANDER ZHAO
ACTS IN DEFEAT?
DISGRACEFUL.
EVEN IN EXILE,
MY NEPHEW
IS MORE HONORABLE
THAN YOU.
THANKS AGAIN
FOR THE TEA.
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
DID YOU REALLY
MEAN THAT, UNCLE?
OF COURSE.
I TOLD YOU
GINSENG TEA
IS MY FAVORITE.
Katara: AANG,
I KNOW YOU'RE UPSET,
AND I KNOW
HOW HARD IT IS
TO LOSE
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
I WENT THROUGH
THE SAME THING
WHEN I LOST MY MOM.
MONK GYATSO
AND THE OTHER
AIRBENDERS
MAY BE GONE,
BUT YOU STILL
HAVE A FAMILY.
SOKKA AND I,
WE'RE YOUR FAMILY NOW.
KATARA AND I AREN'T GONNA
LET ANYTHING
HAPPEN TO YOU.
PROMISE.
[SIGH]
I'M SORRY.
IT'S OK.
IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
BUT YOU WERE RIGHT.
AND IF FIREBENDERS
FOUND THIS TEMPLE,
THAT MEANS
THEY FOUND
THE OTHER ONES, TOO.
I REALLY AM
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
EVERYTHING'S
PACKED.
YOU READY
TO GO?
HOW IS ROKU
SUPPOSED TO HELP ME
IF I CAN'T
TALK TO HIM?
MAYBE
YOU'LL FIND A WAY.
♪♪
[CHOMPING]
MM! MM!
LOOKS LIKE YOU MADE
A NEW FRIEND, SOKKA.
CAN'T TALK. MUST EAT.
HEY, LITTLE GUY.
[CHATTERS]
YOU, ME, AND APPA--
WE'RE ALL THAT'S LEFT
OF THIS PLACE.
WE HAVE TO STICK TOGETHER.
KATARA, SOKKA,
SAY HELLO TO THE NEWEST
MEMBER OF OUR FAMILY.
WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA NAME HIM?
MOMO.
[LAUGHTER]
♪