Katara: WATER, EARTH,
FIRE, AIR...
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
BUT BEFORE I LEARN WATERBENDING,
WE HAVE SOME SERIOUS
BUSINESS TO ATTEND TO.
HERE WE'LL RIDE
THE HOPPING LLAMAS.
THEN WAY OVER HERE
WE'LL SURF ON THE BACKS
OF GIANT KOI FISH.
YOU'RE JUST
A BANISHED PRINCE.
NO HOME, NO ALLIES.
YOUR OWN FATHER
DOESN'T EVEN WANT YOU.
YOU'RE WRONG.
ONCE I DELIVER THE AVATAR
TO MY FATHER,
HE WILL WELCOME ME HOME
WITH HONOR
AND RESTORE
MY RIGHTFUL PLACE
ON THE THRONE.
Katara: WHEN
THE AVATAR DIES,
HE'S REINCARNATED
INTO THE NEXT NATION
IN THE CYCLE.
Aang: FIREBENDERS?
GYATSO.
I REALLY AM
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
THE ONLY REASON
YOU SHOULD BE
INTERRUPTING ME
IS IF YOU HAVE NEWS
ABOUT THE AVATAR.
WELL, THERE IS NEWS,
PRINCE ZUKO,
BUT YOU MIGHT NOT
LIKE IT.
DON'T GET TOO UPSET.
UNCLE, YOU TAUGHT ME
THAT KEEPING A LEVEL HEAD
IS A SIGN
OF A GREAT LEADER.
NOW, WHATEVER
YOU HAVE TO SAY,
I'M SURE I CAN TAKE IT.
OK, THEN.
WE HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE HE IS.
WHAT?
YOU REALLY
SHOULD OPEN A WINDOW
IN HERE.
GIVE ME THE MAP!
THERE HAVE BEEN
MULTIPLE SIGHTINGS
OF THE AVATAR,
BUT HE IS IMPOSSIBLE
TO TRACK DOWN.
HOW AM I GOING TO
FIND HIM, UNCLE?
HE IS CLEARLY A MASTER
OF EVASIVE MANEUVERING.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHERE YOU'RE GOING, DO YOU?
WELL, I KNOW
IT'S NEAR WATER.
Sokka: I GUESS
WE'RE GETTING CLOSE, THEN.
MOMO, MARBLES,
PLEASE.
HEY, KATARA,
CHECK OUT THIS
AIRBENDING TRICK.
THAT'S GREAT, AANG.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN
LOOK.
THAT'S GREAT.
BUT I'M NOT
DOING IT NOW.
STOP BUGGING HER,
AIRHEAD.
YOU NEED TO
GIVE GIRLS SPACE
WHEN THEY DO
THEIR SEWING.
WHAT DOES ME BEING A GIRL
HAVE TO DO WITH SEWING?
SIMPLE. GIRLS ARE BETTER
AT FIXING PANTS THAN GUYS,
AND GUYS ARE BETTER
AT HUNTING AND FIGHTING
AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
IT'S JUST THE NATURAL
ORDER OF THINGS.
ALL DONE WITH YOUR PANTS,
AND LOOK WHAT
A GREAT JOB I DID.
WAIT!
I WAS JUST KIDDING!
I CAN'T WEAR THESE!
KATARA, PLEASE!
RELAX, SOKKA.
WHERE WE'RE GOING,
YOU WON'T NEED
ANY PANTS.
Sokka: WE JUST MADE
A PIT STOP YESTERDAY.
SHOULDN'T WE GET
A LITTLE MORE FLYING DONE
BEFORE WE CAMP OUT?
HE'S RIGHT.
AT THIS RATE, WE WON'T GET
TO THE NORTH POLE
UNTIL SPRING.
BUT APPA'S TIRED
ALREADY,
AREN'T YOU, BOY?
[GRUNTS]
I SAID,
"AREN'T YOU, BOY?"
[YAWNS]
YEAH, THAT WAS
REAL CONVINCING.
STILL,
HARD TO ARGUE
WITH A 10-TON
MAGICAL MONSTER.
LOOK!
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE--
ELEPHANT KOI,
AND I'M GOING TO
RIDE IT.
KATARA, YOU'VE GOT TO
WATCH ME.
COLD!
[LAUGHING]
WOO!
YEAH!
WOO-HOO!
HE LOOKS PRETTY GOOD
OUT THERE.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
THE FISH IS DOING
ALL THE WORK.
NO, APPA!
DON'T EAT THAT!
AW, MAN.
THERE'S SOMETHING
IN THE WATER!
WHAT'S WRONG?
AANG'S IN TROUBLE.
AANG!
GET OUT OF THERE!
GET BACK HERE, AANG!
COME IN!
[YELLS]
[GASPING]
AAH!
WHAT WAS THAT THING?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, LET'S NOT
STICK AROUND
TO FIND OUT.
TIME TO HIT
THE ROAD.
OR WE COULD STAY AWHILE.
Man: YOU 3 HAVE SOME
EXPLAINING TO DO.
Girl: AND IF YOU DON'T
ANSWER ALL OUR QUESTIONS,
WE'RE THROWING YOU
BACK IN THE WATER
WITH THE UNAGI.
SHOW YOURSELVES,
COWARDS!
WHO ARE YOU?
WHERE ARE THE MEN
WHO AMBUSHED US?
THERE WERE NO MEN.
WE AMBUSHED YOU.
NOW TELL US,
WHO ARE YOU
AND WHAT
ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WAIT A SECOND. THERE'S NO WAY
A BUNCH OF GIRLS
TOOK US DOWN.
A BUNCH OF GIRLS,
HUH?
THE UNAGI'S GOING TO
EAT WELL TONIGHT.
NO, DON'T HURT HIM!
HE DIDN'T MEAN IT!
MY BROTHER'S JUST
AN IDIOT SOMETIMES.
Aang: IT'S MY FAULT.
I'M SORRY WE CAME HERE.
I WANTED TO RIDE
THE ELEPHANT KOI.
HOW DO WE KNOW
YOU'RE NOT
FIRE NATION SPIES?
KYOSHI STAYED OUT
OF THE WAR SO FAR
AND WE INTEND
TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
THIS ISLAND IS NAMED
FOR KYOSHI?
I KNOW KYOSHI.
HA!
HOW COULD YOU
POSSIBLY KNOW HER?
AVATAR KYOSHI
WAS BORN HERE
400 YEARS AGO.
SHE'S BEEN DEAD
FOR CENTURIES.
I KNOW HER
BECAUSE I'M THE AVATAR.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THE LAST AVATAR
WAS AN AIRBENDER
WHO DISAPPEARED
100 YEARS AGO.
THAT'S ME.
THROW THE IMPOSTOR
TO THE UNAGI.
AANG, DO SOME
AIRBENDING.
[GIRLS GASPING]
Woman: WOW.
Second woman:
THAT'S AMAZING.
IT'S TRUE.
YOU ARE THE AVATAR.
NOW, CHECK THIS OUT.
[CHEERING]
DID YOU HEAR THE NEWS?
THE AVATAR'S ON KYOSHI.
HUH?
[NO AUDIO]
THE AVATAR'S ON
KYOSHI ISLAND?
UNCLE,
READY THE RHINOS.
HE'S NOT GETTING
AWAY FROM ME
THIS TIME.
ARE YOU GOING TO
FINISH THAT?
I WAS GOING TO
SAVE IT FOR LATER!
ALL RIGHT!
DESSERT FOR
BREAKFAST!
THESE PEOPLE
SURE KNOW HOW TO
TREAT AN AVATAR.
MM!
KATARA,
YOU'VE GOT TO
TRY THESE.
WELL, MAYBE JUST A BITE.
SOKKA, WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM?
EAT!
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
BUT YOU'RE ALWAYS HUNGRY.
HE'S JUST UPSET
BECAUSE A BUNCH OF GIRLS
KICKED HIS BUTT
YESTERDAY.
THEY SNUCK UP
ON ME!
RIGHT, AND THEN
THEY KICKED YOUR BUTT.
SNEAK ATTACKS
DON'T COUNT.
TIE ME UP
WITH ROPES...
I'LL SHOW THEM
A THING OR TWO.
I'M NOT SCARED
OF ANY GIRLS.
WHO DO THEY THINK
THEY ARE, ANYWAY?
MM! THIS IS TASTY.
WHAT'S HE SO ANGRY ABOUT?
IT'S GREAT HERE.
THEY'RE GIVING US
THE ROYAL TREATMENT.
HEY, DON'T GET
TOO COMFORTABLE.
IT'S RISKY FOR US
TO STAY IN ONE PLACE
FOR VERY LONG.
I'M SURE WE'LL BE FINE.
BESIDES,
DID YOU SEE HOW HAPPY
I'M MAKING THIS TOWN?
THEY'RE EVEN CLEANING UP
THAT STATUE IN MY HONOR.
WELL, IT'S NICE
TO SEE YOU EXCITED
ABOUT BEING
THE AVATAR.
I JUST HOPE
IT DOESN'T ALL GO
TO YOUR HEAD.
COME ON,
YOU KNOW ME
BETTER THAN THAT.
I'M JUST A SIMPLE MONK.
[GIRLS SHRIEKING]
Woman: THERE HE IS!
THERE HE IS! OH!
[WOMEN SHRIEKING]
[GASPING]
Man: HMM,
PAINTING THE AVATAR.
THAT'S EASY ENOUGH.
OH, THERE'S
ANOTHER ONE.
WELL, I'LL MAKE
AN ADJUSTMENT
HERE AND--
THERE'S MORE.
I--
[GIGGLING]
OOH!
HEH HEH!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I GOT BEAT UP BY
A BUNCH OF GIRLS.
SORRY, LADIES.
DIDN'T MEAN TO INTERRUPT
YOUR DANCE LESSON.
I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR SOMEWHERE
TO GET A LITTLE WORKOUT.
WELL, YOU'RE IN
THE RIGHT PLACE.
SORRY ABOUT YESTERDAY.
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE FRIENDS
WITH THE AVATAR.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I MEAN, NORMALLY
I'D HOLD A GRUDGE,
BUT SEEING AS YOU GUYS
ARE A BUNCH OF GIRLS,
I'LL MAKE AN EXCEPTION.
I SHOULD HOPE SO.
A BIG, STRONG MAN
LIKE YOU,
WE WOULDN'T STAND
A CHANCE.
TRUE, BUT DON'T FEEL BAD.
AFTER ALL,
I'M THE BEST WARRIOR
IN MY VILLAGE.
WOW. BEST WARRIOR, HUH?
IN YOUR WHOLE VILLAGE?
MAYBE YOU'D BE
KIND ENOUGH
TO GIVE US A LITTLE
DEMONSTRATION.
OH, WELL,
I MEAN, I--
COME ON, GIRLS, WOULDN'T YOU
LIKE HIM TO SHOW US SOME MOVES?
[CHUCKLING]
WELL, IF THAT'S
WHAT YOU WANT,
I'D BE HAPPY TO.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU STAND OVER THERE.
NOW, THIS MAY BE
A LITTLE TOUGH,
BUT TRY TO BLOCK ME.
OW!
[CHUCKLES]
GOOD.
OF COURSE,
I WAS GOING EASY ON YOU.
OF COURSE.
LET'S SEE
IF YOU CAN HANDLE THIS!
OUCH!
OH!
THAT DOES IT!
[SHOUTING]
ANYTHING ELSE
YOU WANT TO TEACH US?
[GIRLS LAUGHING]
THERE SHE IS GIRLS,
ME IN A PAST LIFE.
[GIRLS GASPING]
YOU WERE PRETTY.
EXCUSE ME FOR A SECOND,
LADIES.
OH, GOOD. CAN YOU HELP ME
CARRY THIS
BACK TO THE ROOM?
IT'S A LITTLE HEAVY.
ACTUALLY,
I CAN'T RIGHT NOW.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU CAN'T?
I PROMISED THE GIRLS
I'D GIVE THEM
A RIDE ON APPA.
WHY DON'T YOU COME
WITH US?
IT'LL BE FUN.
WATCHING YOU SHOW OFF
FOR A BUNCH OF GIRLS
DOES NOT SOUND
LIKE FUN.
WELL, NEITHER
DOES CARRYING
YOUR BASKET.
IT'S NOT MY BASKET.
THESE SUPPLIES
ARE FOR OUR TRIP.
I TOLD YOU,
WE HAVE TO LEAVE
KYOSHI SOON.
I DON'T WANT TO
LEAVE KYOSHI YET.
I CAN'T PUT
MY FINGER ON IT,
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING
I REALLY LIKE
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
[GIGGLING]
WHAT'S TAKING YOU
SO LONG, AANGIE?
AANGIE?
JUST A SECOND, KOKO.
SIMPLE MONK, HUH?
I THOUGHT YOU PROMISED ME
THIS AVATAR STUFF
WOULDN'T GO TO YOUR HEAD.
IT DIDN'T. YOU
KNOW WHAT I THINK?
YOU JUST
DON'T WANT TO COME
BECAUSE YOU'RE JEALOUS.
JEALOUS? OF WHAT?
JEALOUS THAT
WE'RE HAVING SO MUCH
FUN WITHOUT YOU.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
IT IS A LITTLE
RIDICULOUS,
BUT I UNDERSTAND.
UGH!
[GIGGLING]
UH, HEY, SUKI.
HOPING FOR ANOTHER
DANCE LESSON?
NO, I--
WELL, LET ME EXPLAIN.
SPIT IT OUT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I WOULD BE HONORED
IF YOU WOULD TEACH ME.
EVEN IF I'M A GIRL?
I'M SORRY
IF I INSULTED YOU EARLIER.
I WAS WRONG.
WE NORMALLY DON'T
TEACH OUTSIDERS,
LET ALONE BOYS.
PLEASE
MAKE AN EXCEPTION.
I WON'T LET YOU DOWN.
ALL RIGHT,
BUT YOU HAVE TO FOLLOW
ALL OF OUR TRADITIONS.
OF COURSE.
AND I MEAN ALL OF THEM.
DO I REALLY
HAVE TO WEAR THIS?
IT FEELS A LITTLE...
GIRLY.
IT'S A WARRIOR'S
UNIFORM.
YOU SHOULD BE PROUD.
THE SILK THREAD
SYMBOLIZES
THE BRAVE BLOOD
THAT FLOWS THROUGH
OUR VEINS.
THE GOLD INSIGNIA
REPRESENTS
THE HONOR OF
THE WARRIOR'S HEART.
BRAVERY AND HONOR.
HEY, SOKKA.
NICE DRESS.
KATARA, REMEMBER HOW
THE UNAGI ALMOST
GOT ME YESTERDAY?
YEAH.
WELL, I'M GOING TO
GO RIDE IT NOW.
IT'S GOING TO
BE REAL DANGEROUS.
GOOD FOR YOU.
YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO STOP ME?
NOPE. HAVE FUN.
I WILL.
GREAT.
I KNOW IT'S GREAT.
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU KNOW.
I'M GLAD
YOU'RE GLAD.
GOOD!
FINE!
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
MASTER IT IN ONE DAY.
EVEN I'M NOT THAT GOOD.
I THINK I'M STARTING
TO GET IT.
IT'S NOT ABOUT STRENGTH.
OUR TECHNIQUE IS ABOUT
USING YOUR OPPONENT'S
FORCE AGAINST THEM.
LOOSEN UP.
THINK OF THE FAN
AS AN EXTENSION
OF YOUR ARM.
WAIT FOR AN OPENING
AND THEN--
HMM.
I FELL ON PURPOSE
TO MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER.
I GOT YOU!
ADMIT I GOT YOU!
OK, IT WAS A LUCKY SHOT.
LET'S SEE
IF YOU CAN DO IT AGAIN.
WHAT'S TAKING
SO LONG?
I'M SURE IT WILL BE HERE
ANY SECOND.
UM, WHAT ABOUT THIS?
NOT THAT AGAIN.
BORING.
WHERE'S UNAGI?
IT'S GETTING
LATE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
DON'T LEAVE!
SORRY, AANG!
MAYBE NEXT TIME!
KATARA,
YOU SHOWED UP!
I WANTED TO MAKE SURE
YOU WERE SAFE.
YOU REALLY
HAD ME WORRIED.
BACK THERE
YOU ACTED LIKE
YOU DIDN'T CARE.
I'M SORRY.
ME, TOO.
I DID LET ALL
THAT ATTENTION
GO TO MY HEAD.
I WAS BEING A JERK.
WELL, GET OUT
OF THE WATER
BEFORE YOU CATCH A COLD,
YOU BIG JERK!
ON MY WAY!
[YELLING]
[AANG SCREAMING]
HANG ON, AANG!
AAH!
AANG!
Katara: ZUKO!
I WANT THE AVATAR ALIVE.
WAKE UP, AANG.
[COUGHS]
KATARA.
DON'T RIDE THE UNAGI.
NOT FUN.
NOT BAD.
- FIRE BENDERS HAVE LANDED
ON OUR SHORES.
GIRLS, COME QUICKLY!
HEY, I'M NOT A--
OH, WHATEVER.
COME OUT, AVATAR.
YOU CAN'T HIDE FROM ME
FOREVER.
FIND HIM.
I GUESS TRAINING'S OVER.
NICE TRY, AVATAR,
BUT THESE LITTLE GIRLS
CAN'T SAVE YOU.
Aang: HEY, OVER HERE!
FINALLY.
GET INSIDE.
LOOK WHAT I BROUGHT
TO THIS PLACE.
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
YES, IT IS.
THESE PEOPLE GOT
THEIR TOWN DESTROYED
TRYING TO
PROTECT ME.
THEN LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
ZUKO WILL LEAVE KYOSHI
TO FOLLOW US.
I KNOW IT FEELS
WRONG TO RUN,
BUT I THINK
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
I'LL CALL APPA.
THERE'S NO TIME
TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
WHAT ABOUT
"I'M SORRY"?
FOR WHAT?
I TREATED YOU
LIKE A GIRL WHEN I SHOULD HAVE
TREATED YOU
LIKE A WARRIOR.
I AM A WARRIOR...
BUT I'M A GIRL, TOO.
NOW GET OUT OF HERE.
WE'LL HOLD THEM OFF.
APPA, YIP YIP!
- BACK TO THE SHIP!
DON'T LOSE SIGHT OF THEM!
I KNOW IT'S HARD,
BUT YOU DID
THE RIGHT THING.
ZUKO WOULD'VE DESTROYED
THE WHOLE PLACE
IF WE STAYED.
THEY'RE GOING TO
BE OK, AANG.
Katara:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THANK YOU, AVATAR.
I KNOW, I KNOW,
THAT WAS STUPID
AND DANGEROUS.
YES, IT WAS.
♪