Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED, AND MY BROTHER
AND I DISCOVERED THE NEW
AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF!
Katara: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
I'M THE AVATAR.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THE LAST AVATAR
WAS AN AIRBENDER
WHO DISAPPEARED
100 YEARS AGO.
THAT'S ME.
I HAVE FRIENDS
ALL OVER THE WORLD,
EVEN IN THE FIRE NATION.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANY WAR.
- SEND WORD
TO THE FIRE LORD
IMMEDIATELY.
THE AVATAR HAS RETURNED.
- MONK GYATSO AND THE OTHER
AIRBENDERS MAY BE GONE,
BUT YOU STILL HAVE A FAMILY.
SOKKA AND I, WE'RE
YOUR FAMILY NOW!
I REALLY AM
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
THE EARTH KINGDOM
CITY OF OMASHU!
I USED TO ALWAYS
COME HERE TO VISIT MY
FRIEND BUMI.
WOW! WE DON'T HAVE CITIES LIKE
THIS IN THE SOUTH POLE.
THEY HAVE BUILDINGS
HERE THAT DON'T MELT.
WELL, LET'S GO,
SLOWPOKES.
THE REAL FUN
IS INSIDE THE CITY!
WAIT, AANG.
IT COULD BE DANGEROUS IF PEOPLE
FIND OUT YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
YOU NEED A DISGUISE.
SO, WHAT AM I
SUPPOSED TO DO,
GROW A MUSTACHE?
OH, THIS IS SO ITCHY.
HOW DO YOU LIVE
IN THIS STUFF?
[SNORTS]
GREAT!
NOW YOU LOOK JUST
LIKE MY GRANDFATHER.
TECHNICALLY,
AANG IS 112 YEARS OLD.
NOW, LET'S GET TO SKIPPING,
YOUNG WHIPPERSNAPPERS!
THE BIG CITY AWAITS!
Aang: YOU GUYS ARE
GONNA LOVE OMASHU.
THE PEOPLE HERE ARE
THE FRIENDLIEST IN THE WORLD.
Man: WHAT KIND OF SLUM
DO YOU THINK THIS IS?!
NO! MY CABBAGES!
JUST KEEP SMILING.
HEH HEH HEH.
STATE YOUR BUSINESS!
MY BUSINESS IS
MY BUSINESS, YOUNG MAN,
AND NONE OF YOURS.
I'VE GOT HALF A MIND TO
BEND YOU OVER MY KNEE
AND PADDLE YOUR BACKSIDE.
SETTLE DOWN,
OLD TIMER.
JUST TELL ME
WHO YOU ARE.
NAME'S BONZOO
PIPPENPADLOPSICOPOLIS
THE THIRD.
AND THESE ARE MY GRANDKIDS.
HI. JUNE
PIPPENPADLOPSICOPOLIS.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
YOU SEEM LIKE
A RESPONSIBLE
YOUNG LADY.
SEE THAT YOUR GRANDFATHER
STAYS OUT OF TROUBLE.
ENJOY OMASHU.
WE WILL.
WAIT A MINUTE!
YOU'RE A STRONG YOUNG BOY.
SHOW SOME RESPECT
FOR THE ELDERLY
AND CARRY YOUR
GRANDFATHER'S BAG.
GOOD IDEA.
Aang: THIS IS THE OMASHU
DELIVERY SYSTEM--
MILES AND MILES OF
TUBES AND CHUTES.
EARTHBENDING BRINGS
THE PACKAGES UP,
AND GRAVITY
BRINGS THEM DOWN.
GREAT, SO THEY GET
THEIR MAIL ON TIME.
THEY DO GET THEIR
MAIL ON TIME.
BUT MY FRIEND BUMI
FOUND A BETTER USE
FOR THESE CHUTES.
LOOK AROUND YOU!
WHAT DO YOU SEE?!
UM...
THE MAIL SYSTEM.
INSTEAD OF SEEING WHAT
THEY WANT YOU TO SEE,
YOU GOTTA OPEN
YOUR BRAIN
TO THE POSSIBILITIES.
A PACKAGE-SENDING SYSTEM?
THE WORLD'S GREATEST
SUPER SLIDE!
BUMI, YOU'RE
A MAD GENIUS.
[LAUGHS]
[SNORTS]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
YEAH! HA HA HA HA!
ONE RIDE...
THEN WE'RE OFF TO
THE NORTH POLE...
AIRBENDER'S HONOR.
THIS SOUNDED LIKE
FUN AT FIRST,
BUT NOW THAT
I'M HERE,
I'M STARTING TO HAVE
SECOND THOUGHTS!
[LAUGHING]
[SCREAMING]
Aang: YEAH!
HA HA HA HA!
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
I'M ON IT!
[SCREAMING]
MEN, YOU'LL BE GOING
OFF TO COMBAT SOON.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT YOU
BE PREPARED FOR ANYTHING.
AANG, DO SOMETHING!
USE YOUR AIRBENDING!
YEAH! GOOD IDEA!
THAT WILL MAKE US
GO EVEN FASTER.
[SCREAMING]
[SIGHS]
Aang: SORRY!
[ALL SCREAM]
[HUMMING]
MY CABBAGES!
YOU'RE GONNA
PAY FOR THIS!
TWO CABBAGES, PLEASE.
HMM?
YOUR MAJESTY,
THESE JUVENILES
WERE ARRESTED
FOR VANDALISM,
TRAVELING UNDER
FALSE PRETENSES,
AND MALICIOUS
DESTRUCTION
OF CABBAGES.
OFF WITH
THEIR HEADS!
ONE FOR EACH
HEAD OF CABBAGE!
SILENCE!
ONLY THE KING CAN
PASS DOWN JUDGMENT.
WHAT IS YOUR
JUDGMENT, SIRE?
HMM.
[STAMMERING]
[WHISTLING]
THROW THEM...
A FEAST.
UGH!
HUH?
[CHUCKLES]
THE PEOPLE IN MY CITY
HAVE GOTTEN FAT
FROM TOO MANY FEASTS.
SO, I HOPE YOU LIKE YOUR
CHICKEN WITH NO SKIN.
THANKS, BUT I DON'T
EAT MEAT.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I BET YOU LIKE MEAT.
[GRUNTS]
IS IT JUST ME,
OR IS THIS GUY'S CROWN
A LITTLE CROOKED?
SO, TELL ME,
YOUNG BALD ONE,
WHERE ARE
YOU FROM?
I'M FROM KANGAROO ISLAND.
OH, KANGAROO ISLAND, EH?
I HEAR THAT PLACE
IS REALLY HOPPING.
[MAN COUGHS]
[LAUGHS]
WHAT?
IT WAS
PRETTY FUNNY.
[YAWNS]
ALL THESE GOOD JOKES
ARE MAKING ME TIRED.
GUESS IT'S TIME
TO HIT THE HAY.
[GASPS]
THERE'S AN AIRBENDER
IN OUR PRESENCE,
AND NOT JUST
ANY AIRBENDER--
THE AVATAR.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO SAY FOR YOURSELF,
MR. PIPPENPADLOPSICOPOLIS?
OK, YOU CAUGHT ME.
I'M THE AVATAR...
DOING MY AVATAR THING,
KEEPING THE WORLD SAFE.
EVERYTHING CHECKS OUT.
NO FIREBENDERS HERE.
SO, GOOD WORK, EVERYBODY.
LOVE EACH OTHER,
RESPECT ALL LIFE,
AND DON'T RUN
WITH YOUR SPEARS.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME!
Katara: YOU CAN'T
KEEP US HERE.
LET US LEAVE!
LETTUCE LEAF?
WE'RE IN
SERIOUS TROUBLE.
THIS GUY
IS NUTS.
TOMORROW, THE AVATAR WILL
FACE 3 DEADLY CHALLENGES.
BUT FOR NOW, THE GUARDS WILL
SHOW YOU TO YOUR CHAMBER.
MY LIEGE,
DO YOU MEAN
THE GOOD CHAMBER
OR THE BAD CHAMBER?
THE NEWLY-REFURBISHED CHAMBER.
WAIT. WHICH ONE ARE
WE TALKING ABOUT?
THE ONE THAT USED TO
BE THE BAD CHAMBER...
UNTIL THE RECENT
REFURBISHING, THAT IS.
OF COURSE, WE'VE BEEN
CALLING IT THE NEW CHAMBER,
BUT WE REALLY
SHOULD NUMBER THEM.
UH...
TAKE THEM TO
THE REFURBISHED CHAMBER
THAT WAS ONCE BAD.
Katara: THIS IS
A PRISON CELL?
BUT IT'S SO NICE.
HE DID SAY IT WAS
NEWLY REFURBISHED.
NICE OR NOT,
WE'RE PRISONERS.
I WONDER WHAT THESE
CHALLENGES ARE GONNA BE.
WE'RE NOT STICKING
AROUND TO FIND OUT.
THERE'S GOTTA BE
SOME WAY OUT OF HERE.
THE AIR VENTS!
IF YOU THINK
WE'RE GONNA FIT
THROUGH THERE,
YOU'RE CRAZIER
THAN THAT KING.
WE CAN'T.
BUT MOMO CAN.
MOMO, I NEED
YOU TO FIND APPA
AND BUST US
OUT OF HERE.
[GROANS]
GO ON, BOY!
GET APPA!
EH, HOW WAS APPA SUPPOSED
TO SAVE US ANYWAY?
APPA IS A 10-TON
FLYING BISON.
I THINK HE COULD FIGURE
SOMETHING OUT.
WELL, NO POINT
ARGUING ABOUT IT NOW.
GET SOME REST, AANG.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'LL
NEED IT FOR TOMORROW.
[SNORING]
SOKKA? KATARA?!
WHERE ARE MY FRIENDS?!
THE KING WILL FREE THEM
IF YOU COMPLETE
YOUR CHALLENGES.
AND IF I FAIL?
HE DIDN'T SAY.
YOUR STAFF, PLEASE?
FIRST, AVATAR,
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF MY NEW OUTFIT?
I WANT YOUR HONEST OPINION.
[MAN COUGHS]
I'M WAITING.
I...
GUESS IT'S FINE.
EXCELLENT.
YOU'VE PASSED
THE FIRST TEST.
REALLY?
WELL...
NOT ONE OF
THE DEADLY TESTS.
THE REAL CHALLENGES
ARE MUCH MORE...
CHALLENGING.
I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR YOUR CRAZY GAMES.
GIVE ME MY FRIENDS BACK.
WE'RE LEAVING!
OH, I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT REFUSE,
SO I WILL GIVE YOUR FRIENDS
SOME SPECIAL SOUVENIRS.
THOSE DELIGHTFUL RINGS
ARE MADE OF
PURE GENOMITE...
ALSO KNOWN AS
CREEPING CRYSTAL.
IT'S CRYSTAL THAT GROWS
REMARKABLY FAST.
BY NIGHTFALL,
YOUR FRIENDS WILL BE
COMPLETELY COVERED IN IT.
TERRIBLE FATE, REALLY.
I CAN STOP IT,
BUT ONLY IF YOU COOPERATE.
AGH! IT'S ALREADY
CREEPING!
I'LL DO
WHAT YOU WANT.
HMM!
King: HA HA HA HA HA!
IT SEEMS I'VE LOST
MY LUNCHBOX KEY,
AND I'M HUNGRY.
OH, THERE IT IS!
WOULD YOU MIND
FETCHING IT FOR ME?
OOH!
CLIMBING THE LADDER.
NO ONE'S THOUGHT
OF THAT BEFORE!
AAH!
[SCREAMING]
[WHIMPERS]
THAT'S RIGHT.
KEEP DIVING HEAD IN.
I'M SURE IT WILL
WORK EVENTUALLY.
HUH?!
Aang: THERE!
ENJOY YOUR LUNCH!
I WANT MY FRIENDS
BACK NOW!
UH, NOT YET.
I NEED HELP WITH
ANOTHER MATTER.
IT SEEMS I'VE LOST
MY PET FLOPSY.
OK, FOUND HIM.
BRING HIM TO ME.
DADDY WANTS A KISS
FROM FLOPSY.
COME HERE, FLOPSY.
HEH HEH.
[SNARLING]
FLOPSY, WAIT!
FLOPSY!
[LAUGHING]
WAIT A MINUTE.
FLOPSY?
[SCREAMING]
FLOPSY!
OH, THAT'S A GOOD BOY.
YES! WHO HAS A SOFT BELLY?!
GUYS, ARE YOU OK?
OTHER THAN
THE CRYSTAL SLOWLY
ENCASING MY ENTIRE BODY,
DOING GREAT.
OH, YES.
COME ON. I'M READY FOR
THE NEXT CHALLENGE.
AH! HA HA HA HA HA!
YOUR FINAL TEST
IS A DUEL.
AND, AS
A SPECIAL TREAT,
YOU MAY CHOOSE
YOUR OPPONENT.
POINT AND CHOOSE.
SO, YOU'RE SAYING
WHOEVER I POINT TO...
THAT'S THE PERSON
I GET TO FIGHT?
CHOOSE WISELY.
Aang: I...
CHOOSE...
YOU.
HA HA.
WRONG CHOICE.
[GRUNTING]
WHOA!
OOF!
[LAUGHING]
YOU THOUGHT I WAS
A FRAIL OLD MAN,
BUT I'M THE MOST
POWERFUL EARTHBENDER
YOU'LL EVER SEE.
CAN I FIGHT THE GUY
WITH THE AX INSTEAD?
THERE ARE
NO TAKE-BACKSIES
IN MY KINGDOM.
YOU MIGHT NEED THIS.
TYPICAL AIRBENDER
TACTIC--
AVOID AND EVADE.
I'D HOPED THE AVATAR
WOULD BE LESS
PREDICTABLE.
DON'T YOU HAVE ANY
SURPRISES FOR ME?
SOONER OR LATER,
YOU'LL HAVE TO
STRIKE BACK.
OH, YOU'LL
HAVE TO BE
A LITTLE MORE
CREATIVE THAN THAT.
DID SOMEONE LEAVE
THE WINDOWS OPEN?
IT FEELS A LITTLE
DRAFTY IN HERE.
ARE YOU HOPING
I'LL CATCH A COLD?
HOW ARE YOU
GOING TO GET ME
FROM WAY
OVER THERE?
[YELLING]
OOF!
[SCREAMS]
AAH!
HUH.
HA HA.
WELL DONE, AVATAR.
YOU FIGHT WITH MUCH
FIRE IN YOUR HEART.
HUH?
YOU'VE PASSED
ALL MY TESTS.
NOW, YOU MUST
ANSWER ONE QUESTION.
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
YOU SAID YOU WOULD
RELEASE MY FRIENDS
IF I FINISH YOUR TESTS.
OH, BUT WHAT'S
THE POINT OF TESTS
IF YOU DON'T LEARN
ANYTHING?
OH, COME ON!
ANSWER THIS ONE QUESTION
AND I WILL SET
YOUR FRIENDS FREE.
WHAT IS MY NAME?
FROM THE LOOKS
OF YOUR FRIENDS,
I'D SAY YOU ONLY
HAVE A FEW MINUTES.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO KNOW HIS NAME?
THINK ABOUT
THE CHALLENGES.
MAYBE IT'S
SOME KIND OF RIDDLE.
I GOT IT!
YEAH?!
HE'S AN EARTHBENDER,
RIGHT?
ROCKY...
[MAN COUGHS]
YOU KNOW, BECAUSE
OF ALL THE ROCKS.
WE'RE GONNA KEEP TRYING,
BUT THAT IS
A GOOD BACKUP.
OK, SO BACK TO
THE CHALLENGES.
I GOT A KEY FROM
A WATERFALL,
I SAVED HIS PET,
AND I HAD A DUEL.
AND WHAT DID YOU LEARN?
WELL, EVERYTHING WAS
DIFFERENT THAN I EXPECTED.
AND...
WELL...
THEY WEREN'T
STRAIGHTFORWARD.
TO SOLVE EACH TEST,
I HAD TO THINK DIFFERENTLY
THAN I USUALLY WOULD.
I KNOW HIS NAME.
I SOLVED THE QUESTION
THE SAME WAY I SOLVED
THE CHALLENGES.
AS YOU SAID
A LONG TIME AGO,
I HAD TO OPEN MY BRAIN
TO THE POSSIBILITIES.
[LAUGHS, SNORTS]
BUMI, YOU'RE
A MAD GENIUS.
OH, AANG,
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
YOU HAVEN'T
CHANGED A BIT...
LITERALLY.
UH, OVER HERE.
A LITTLE HELP.
GENOMITE IS MADE
OF ROCK CANDY.
[CRUNCH]
DELICIOUS!
SO, THIS CRAZY KING
IS YOUR OLD FRIEND BUMI?
WHO YOU
CALLING OLD?!
OK, I'M OLD.
WHY DID YOU DO ALL THIS
INSTEAD OF JUST TELLING
AANG WHO YOU WERE?
FIRST OF ALL, IT'S PRETTY FUN
MESSING WITH PEOPLE.
HA HA.
BUT I DO HAVE A REASON.
AANG, YOU HAVE
A DIFFICULT TASK AHEAD.
THE WORLD HAS CHANGED IN
THE 100 YEARS YOU'VE BEEN GONE.
IT'S THE DUTY OF THE AVATAR
TO RESTORE
BALANCE TO THE WORLD
BY DEFEATING
FIRE LORD OZAI.
YOU HAVE MUCH TO LEARN.
YOU MUST MASTER
THE 4 ELEMENTS
AND CONFRONT THE FIRE LORD.
AND WHEN YOU DO,
I HOPE YOU WILL THINK
LIKE A MAD GENIUS.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE IN GOOD HANDS.
YOU'LL NEED YOUR FRIENDS
TO HELP YOU DEFEAT
THE FIRE NATION.
AND YOU'LL
NEED MOMO, TOO.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR WISDOM.
BUT BEFORE WE LEAVE,
I HAVE A CHALLENGE FOR YOU.
YEAH!
WHOO!
[LAUGHING]
[CRASH]
Man: MY CABBAGES!
♪