Katara, voice-over:
WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED WHEN
THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
- IT'S BEEN SO LONG
SINCE I'VE HAD HOPE,
BUT YOU BROUGHT IT BACK TO
LIFE, MY LITTLE WATERBENDER.
AANG IS THE AVATAR.
YOU BOTH FOUND HIM
FOR A REASON.
NOW YOUR DESTINIES
ARE INTERTWINED WITH HIS.
ACCORDING TO LEGEND,
YOU NEED TO FIRST
MASTER WATER,
THEN EARTH, THEN
FIRE, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHAT
THE MONKS TOLD ME.
WELL, IF WE GO
TO THE NORTH POLE,
YOU CAN MASTER
WATERBENDING.
WE COULD LEARN IT TOGETHER!
THERE HAVE BEEN
MULTIPLE SIGHTINGS
OF THE AVATAR,
BUT HE IS IMPOSSIBLE
TO TRACK DOWN.
THIS COWARD'S HUNDRED
YEARS IN HIDING ARE OVER.
[BIRDS SINGING]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
- GREAT. YOU'RE BACK.
WHAT'S FOR DINNER?
WE'VE GOT
A FEW OPTIONS.
FIRST, ROUND NUTS AND SOME KIND
OF OVAL-SHAPED NUTS.
AND SOME ROCK-SHAPED NUTS
THAT MIGHT JUST BE ROCKS.
DIG IN.
SERIOUSLY,
WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
[PURRING]
[BOOM]
Sokka: WHAT WAS THAT?
Aang: IT'S COMING
FROM OVER THERE.
Sokka:
SHOULDN'T WE RUN AWAY FROM
HUGE BOOMS, NOT TOWARD THEM?
[PURRING]
HYAH.
AN EARTHBENDER.
LET'S GO MEET HIM.
HE LOOKS DANGEROUS,
SO WE BETTER APPROACH
CAUTIOUSLY.
HELLO THERE!
I'M KATARA.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
AH!
Aang: NICE TO MEET YOU!
I JUST WANTED TO SAY HI.
HEY, THAT GUY'S
GOT TO BE RUNNING
SOMEWHERE.
MAYBE WE'RE
NEAR A VILLAGE.
AND I BET THAT VILLAGE
HAS A MARKET.
WHICH MEANS
NO NUTS FOR DINNER.
HEY! I WORKED HARD
TO GET THOSE NUTS.
[PURRING]
YEAH, I HATE THEM, TOO.
Aang: GREAT HAT.
I'LL TRADE YOU
SOME NUTS FOR IT.
HEY!
HI, MOM.
WHERE HAVE
YOU BEEN, HARU?
YOU'RE LATE!
GET STARTED
ON YOUR CHORES.
HEY! YOU'RE THAT KID.
AH!
WHY DID YOU
RUN AWAY BEFORE?
UH...YOU MUST
HAVE ME CONFUSED
WITH SOME OTHER KID.
NO, SHE DOESN'T.
WE SAW YOU EARTHBENDING.
THEY SAW YOU
DOING WHAT?
THEY'RE CRAZY,
MOM.
I MEAN,
LOOK AT HOW
THEY'RE DRESSED.
YOU KNOW
HOW DANGEROUS THAT IS.
YOU KNOW WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF THEY CAUGHT YOU EARTHBENDING.
Man: OPEN UP!
[LOUD KNOCKING]
Sokka:
FIRE NATION. ACT NATURAL.
AAH!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I'VE ALREADY
PAID YOU THIS WEEK.
THE TAX JUST DOUBLED.
WE WOULDN'T WANT
AN ACCIDENT, WOULD WE?
FIRE IS SOMETIMES
SO HARD TO CONTROL.
YOU CAN KEEP
THE COPPER ONES.
NICE GUY.
HOW LONG HAS
THE FIRE NATION
BEEN HERE?
FIVE YEARS.
FIRE LORD OZAI
USES OUR TOWN'S
COAL MINES
TO FUEL HIS SHIPS.
THEY'RE THUGS.
THEY STEAL FROM US.
AND EVERYONE HERE
IS TOO MUCH OF A COWARD
TO DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
QUIET, HARU!
DON'T TALK
LIKE THAT!
BUT HARU'S
AN EARTHBENDER.
HE CAN HELP.
EARTHBENDING
IS FORBIDDEN.
IT'S CAUSED
NOTHING BUT MISERY
FOR THIS VILLAGE.
HE MUST NEVER USE
HIS ABILITIES.
HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT?
HARU HAS A GIFT.
ASKING HIM NOT TO EARTHBEND
IS LIKE ASKING ME
NOT TO WATERBEND.
IT'S A PART OF
WHO WE ARE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND THAT HARU
CAN HELP YOU FIGHT BACK.
WHAT CAN THE FIRE NATION
DO TO YOU
THAT THEY
HAVEN'T DONE ALREADY?
THEY COULD TAKE HARU AWAY,
LIKE THEY TOOK HIS FATHER.
Haru: MY MOM SAID
YOU CAN SLEEP HERE TONIGHT.
BUT YOU SHOULD LEAVE
IN THE MORNING.
THANKS. I'LL MAKE
SURE APPA DOESN'T
EAT ALL YOUR HAY.
Katara: I'M SORRY ABOUT
WHAT I SAID EARLIER.
I DIDN'T KNOW ABOUT
YOUR FATHER.
Haru: THAT'S OK.
IT'S FUNNY. THE WAY
YOU WERE TALKING
BACK IN THE STORE,
IT REMINDED ME
OF HIM.
THANKS.
MY FATHER WAS VERY COURAGEOUS.
WHEN THE FIRE NATION INVADED,
HE AND THE OTHER EARTHBENDERS
WERE OUTNUMBERED 10 TO 1.
BUT THEY FOUGHT
BACK ANYWAY.
HE SOUNDS LIKE A GREAT MAN.
AFTER THE ATTACK,
THEY ROUNDED UP MY FATHER
AND EVERY OTHER EARTHBENDER
AND TOOK THEM AWAY.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN THEM SINCE.
SO THAT'S WHY YOU HIDE
YOUR EARTHBENDING.
YEAH.
THE PROBLEM IS,
THE ONLY WAY I CAN FEEL
CLOSE TO MY FATHER NOW
IS WHEN I PRACTICE
MY BENDING.
HE TAUGHT ME
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
SEE THIS NECKLACE?
MY MOTHER GAVE IT TO ME.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I LOST MY MOTHER
IN A FIRE NATION RAID.
THIS NECKLACE IS
ALL I HAVE LEFT OF HER.
IT'S NOT ENOUGH,
IS IT?
NO.
- AAH! HELP!
THE MINE!
AAH...
HELP ME!
[MOANING]
[RUMBLING]
AH! IT'S NOT WORKING.
WE HAVE TO GET HELP.
THERE'S NO TIME.
PULL HARDER!
HARU, THERE'S A WAY
YOU CAN HELP HIM.
I CAN'T.
PLEASE. THERE'S
NO ONE AROUND TO SEE YOU.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY!
AH!
HARU, YOU DID IT!
[PURRING]
IT WAS SO BRAVE OF HARU
TO USE HIS EARTHBENDING
TO HELP THAT OLD MAN.
YOU MUST HAVE
REALLY INSPIRED HIM.
I GUESS SO.
EVERYONE SHOULD
GET SOME SLEEP.
WE'RE LEAVING
AT DAWN.
DAWN? CAN'T WE
SLEEP IN FOR ONCE?
ABSOLUTELY NOT!
THIS VILLAGE IS CRAWLING
WITH FIRE NATION TROOPS.
IF THEY DISCOVER
YOU'RE HERE, AANG,
WE'LL BE EATING
FIREBALLS FOR BREAKFAST.
GOOD NIGHT.
I'D RATHER EAT
FIREBALLS THAN NUTS.
GOOD NIGHT.
[LAUGHING]
AH!
THAT'S HIM!
THAT'S THE EARTHBENDER!
AAH!
THEY TOOK HIM!
THEY TOOK HARU AWAY!
WHAT?
THE OLD MAN TURNED HIM
IN TO THE FIRE NATION.
IT'S ALL MY FAULT.
I FORCED HIM INTO EARTHBENDING.
SLOW DOWN, KATARA.
WHEN DID THIS HAPPEN?
HARU'S MOTHER SAID
THEY CAME FOR HIM
AT MIDNIGHT.
THEN IT'S TOO LATE
TO TRACK HIM.
HE'S LONG GONE.
WE DON'T NEED
TO TRACK HIM.
THE FIRE NATION
IS GOING TO
TAKE ME RIGHT
TO HARU.
AND WHY WOULD
THEY DO THAT?
BECAUSE THEY'RE GOING TO
ARREST ME FOR EARTHBENDING.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE CRAZY
AT FIRST, KATARA,
BUT THIS MIGHT WORK.
THERE ARE VENTILATION
SHAFTS THROUGHOUT THESE MINES.
ALL AANG HAS TO DO IS
SEND AN AIR CURRENT
FROM THAT VENT
TO THIS ONE RIGHT HERE.
THE BOULDER LEVITATES
AND TA-DA--
FAKE EARTHBENDING.
AANG, DID YOU GET
ALL THAT?
SURE, SURE.
I GOT IT.
DO YOU REMEMBER YOUR CUE?
YEAH, YEAH.
JUST RELAX.
YOU'RE TAKING ALL
THE FUN OUT OF THIS.
BY "THIS" DO YOU MEAN
INTENTIONALLY BEING CAPTURED
BY AN ARMY OF
RUTHLESS FIREBENDERS?
EXACTLY.
THAT'S FUN STUFF.
Sokka: HERE THEY COME.
GET IN YOUR PLACES.
UH! GET OUT OF MY WAY,
PIPSQUEAK.
HOW DARE YOU
CALL ME PIPSQUEAK,
YOU GIANT-EARED
CRETIN?
WHAT DID YOU
CALL ME?
A GIANT-EARED
CRETIN.
LOOK AT
THOSE THINGS.
DO HERDS OF ANIMALS
USE THEM FOR SHADE?
YOU BETTER BACK OFF!
SERIOUSLY,
BACK OFF.
I WILL NOT BACK OFF!
I BET ELEPHANTS
GET TOGETHER
AND MAKE FUN
OF HOW LARGE
YOUR EARS ARE.
THAT'S IT!
YOU'RE GOING DOWN.
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHO'S BOSS,
EARTHBENDING STYLE.
I SAID,
"EARTHBENDING STYLE!"
THAT LEMUR.
HE'S EARTHBENDING.
NO, YOU IDIOT.
IT'S THE GIRL.
OH. OF COURSE.
I'LL HOLD HER!
[WHISPERING]
YOU'VE GOT 12 HOURS
TO FIND HARU.
WE'LL BE
RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
MOMO, YOU HAVE
SOME BIG EARS.
[PURRING]
SHE'LL BE FINE, AANG.
KATARA KNOWS WHAT SHE'S DOING.
Man: EARTHBENDERS,
IT IS MY PLEASURE TO WELCOME YOU
ABOARD MY MODEST SHIPYARD.
I AM YOUR WARDEN.
I PREFER TO THINK OF YOU
NOT AS PRISONERS,
BUT AS HONORED GUESTS.
AND I HOPE YOU
COME TO THINK OF ME
AS YOUR HUMBLE
AND CARING HOST.
YOU WILL SUCCEED HERE
IF YOU SIMPLY ABIDE--
[COUGHING]
WHAT KIND OF GUEST DISHONORS
HIS HOST BY INTERRUPTING HIM?
TAKE HIM BELOW.
ONE WEEK IN SOLITARY
WILL IMPROVE HIS MANNERS.
SIMPLY TREAT ME WITH
THE COURTESY I GIVE YOU
AND WE'LL GET ALONG
FAMOUSLY.
YOU WILL NOTICE,
EARTHBENDERS,
THAT THIS RIG IS MADE
ENTIRELY OF METAL.
YOU ARE MILES AWAY
FROM ANY ROCK OR EARTH.
SO, IF YOU HAVE ANY ILLUSIONS
ABOUT EMPLOYING
THAT BRUTISH SAVAGERY
THAT PASSES FOR BENDING
AMONG YOU PEOPLE,
FORGET THEM.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE.
GOOD DAY.
KATARA?
HARU!
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
IT'S MY FAULT
YOU WERE CAPTURED.
I CAME TO RESCUE YOU.
SO YOU GOT
YOURSELF ARRESTED?
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
TO FIND YOU.
YOU'VE GOT GUTS, KATARA.
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT.
COME ON. THERE'S SOMEONE
I WANT YOU TO MEET.
KATARA, THIS IS
MY FATHER, TYRO.
DAD, THIS IS KATARA.
IT'S AN HONOR
TO MEET YOU.
HAVE SOME DINNER, KATARA.
EW.
IT'S NOT AS BAD
AS IT LOOKS.
EEW!
IT'S STILL
PRETTY BAD, THOUGH.
TYRO, THE PRISONERS
ARE COMPLAINING
THERE AREN'T ENOUGH
BLANKETS TO GO AROUND.
I'LL TALK TO THE GUARDS.
IN THE MEANTIME, MAKE SURE
THE ELDERLY ARE TAKEN CARE OF.
THE REST OF US WILL SIMPLY
HAVE TO HOPE FOR WARMER WEATHER.
IF YOU DON'T MIND
ME ASKING,
WHAT'S YOUR
ESCAPE PLAN?
EXCUSE ME?
YOU KNOW, THE PLAN
TO GET EVERYONE
OFF THE RIG?
WHAT IS IT?
MUTINY, SABOTAGE?
THE PLAN?
THE PLAN IS TO SURVIVE,
WAIT OUT THIS WAR,
HOPE THAT ONE DAY
SOME OF US CAN GET BACK HOME
AND FORGET THIS EVER HAPPENED.
HOW CAN YOU SAY THAT?
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU'VE
ALREADY GIVEN UP.
KATARA, I ADMIRE
YOUR COURAGE.
AND I ENVY YOUR YOUTH.
BUT PEOPLE'S LIVES
ARE AT STAKE HERE.
THE WARDEN IS
A RUTHLESS MAN,
AND HE WON'T STAND
FOR ANY REBELLION.
I'M SORRY,
BUT WE'RE POWERLESS.
WE'LL SEE ABOUT THAT.
EARTHBENDERS!
YOU DON'T KNOW ME,
BUT I KNOW OF YOU.
EVERY CHILD IN MY WATER TRIBE
VILLAGE WAS ROCKED TO SLEEP
WITH STORIES OF THE BRAVE
EARTH KINGDOM
AND THE COURAGEOUS EARTHBENDERS
WHO GUARD ITS BORDERS.
SOME OF YOU MAY THINK
THAT THE FIRE NATION
HAS MADE YOU POWERLESS.
YES. THEY HAVE TAKEN AWAY
YOUR ABILITY TO BEND.
BUT THEY CAN'T TAKE AWAY
YOUR COURAGE.
AND IT IS YOUR COURAGE
THEY SHOULD TRULY FEAR,
BECAUSE IT RUNS DEEPER
THAN ANY MINE
YOU'VE BEEN FORCED TO DIG,
ANY OCEAN THAT KEEPS YOU
FAR FROM HOME.
IT IS THE STRENGTH
OF YOUR HEARTS
THAT MAKE YOU WHO YOU ARE,
HEARTS THAT WILL REMAIN UNBROKEN
WHEN ALL ROCK AND STONE
HAS ERODED AWAY.
THE TIME TO FIGHT BACK IS NOW!
I CAN TELL YOU
THE AVATAR HAS RETURNED!
SO REMEMBER YOUR COURAGE,
EARTHBENDERS!
LET US FIGHT FOR OUR FREEDOM!
[MAN COUGHING]
AH!
SHH.
YOUR 12 HOURS ARE UP.
WHERE IS HARU?
WE'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
I CAN'T.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
THERE ARE GUARDS EVERYWHERE.
GET ON!
KATARA, WHAT'S WRONG?
I'M NOT LEAVING.
I'M NOT GIVING UP
ON THESE PEOPLE.
Sokka: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU'RE NOT LEAVING?
WE CAN'T ABANDON
THESE PEOPLE.
THERE HAS TO BE
A WAY TO HELP THEM.
MAYBE SHE'S RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, SOKKA?
I SAY YOU'RE
BOTH CRAZY.
LAST CHANCE.
WE NEED TO LEAVE NOW.
NO.
I HATE WHEN YOU
GET LIKE THIS.
COME ON, WE BETTER HIDE.
[WHISPERING]
GO.
LOOK!
TELL ME EXACTLY
WHAT YOU SAW.
WELL, SIR, IT LOOKED
LIKE A FLYING BISON.
WHAT?
IT WAS A GIANT,
FLYING BUFFALO, SIR,
WITH AN EMPTY SADDLE.
WHICH WAS IT,
A BUFFALO
OR A BISON?
I-I-I'M NOT SURE
WHAT THE DIFFERENCE IS,
BUT THAT'S NOT REALLY
THE POINT, IS IT, SIR?
I'LL DECIDE WHAT
THE POINT IS, FOOL!
AAH!
[SPLASH]
YOU! WAKE UP
THE CAPTAIN! SEARCH
THE ENTIRE RIG!
SIR.
WHAT?
THAT WAS THE CAPTAIN
YOU JUST THREW OVERBOARD, SO--
THEN WAKE UP
SOMEONE I HAVEN'T
THROWN OVERBOARD
AND SEARCH THE RIG.
THERE'S SOMETHING GOING ON HERE,
AND I DON'T LIKE IT.
[PURRING]
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
I WISH I KNEW HOW TO
MAKE A HURRICANE.
THE WARDEN WOULD RUN AWAY,
AND WE WOULD STEAL HIS KEYS.
WOULDN'T HE JUST TAKE
HIS KEYS WITH HIM?
I'M JUST TOSSING
IDEAS AROUND.
I TRIED TALKING
THE EARTHBENDERS
INTO FIGHTING BACK,
BUT IT DIDN'T WORK.
IF THERE WAS JUST
A WAY TO HELP THEM
HELP THEMSELVES.
FOR THAT THEY NEED
SOME KIND OF EARTH
OR SOME ROCK,
SOMETHING THEY CAN BEND.
BUT THIS ENTIRE PLACE
IS MADE OF METAL.
NO, IT'S NOT.
LOOK AT THE SMOKE.
I BET THEY'RE BURNING COAL.
IN OTHER WORDS...
EARTH.
IT'S ALMOST DAWN.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
YOU SURE THIS IS
GONNA WORK?
IT SHOULD.
THESE VENTS REMINDED ME
OF OUR LITTLE TRICK
BACK AT THE VILLAGE.
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE SAME THING,
BUT ON A MUCH
BIGGER SCALE.
THERE'S A HUGE DEPOSIT OF COAL
AT THE BASE OF THIS ISLAND.
AND THE WHOLE SYSTEM
IS VENTILATED.
AANG CLOSED OFF
ALL THE VENTS EXCEPT ONE.
WHEN HE DOES
HIS AIRBENDING,
THE COAL ONLY HAS
ONE PLACE TO GO--
RIGHT BACK HERE.
Man: THERE'S THE INTRUDER!
STAY BACK!
I'M WARNING YOU!
KATARA, STOP.
YOU CAN'T WIN THIS FIGHT.
LISTEN TO HIM WELL,
CHILD.
YOU'RE
ONE MISTAKE AWAY
FROM DYING
WHERE YOU STAND.
[COUGHING]
HERE'S YOUR CHANCE,
EARTHBENDERS!
TAKE IT! YOUR FATE
IS IN YOUR OWN HANDS!
[WARDEN LAUGHING]
FOOLISH GIRL.
YOU THOUGHT A FEW
INSPIRATIONAL WORDS
AND SOME COAL WOULD
CHANGE THESE PEOPLE?
LOOK AT THESE BLANK
HOPELESS FACES.
THEIR SPIRITS
WERE BROKEN
A LONG TIME AGO.
OH, BUT YOU STILL
BELIEVED IN THEM.
HOW SWEET.
THEY'RE A WASTE
OF YOUR ENERGY,
LITTLE GIRL.
YOU FAILED.
GRR.
HYAH!
SHOW NO MERCY!
AAH!
FOR THE EARTH KINGDOM,
ATTACK!
[ALL YELLING]
[SCREAMING]
GET TO THE SHIP!
WE'LL HOLD THEM OFF!
DO NOT LET THEM ESCAPE!
GUYS, THROW ME SOME COAL!
NO, PLEASE.
I CAN'T SWIM.
DON'T WORRY.
I HEAR COWARDS FLOAT.
[SCREAMING]
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR SAVING ME, FOR SAVING US.
ALL IT TOOK WAS
A LITTLE COAL.
IT WASN'T THE COAL,
KATARA.
IT WAS YOU.
THANK YOU FOR HELPING ME
FIND MY COURAGE,
KATARA OF
THE WATER TRIBE.
MY FAMILY
AND EVERYONE HERE
OWES YOU MUCH.
SO, I GUESS
YOU'RE GOING HOME NOW.
YES, TO TAKE BACK
MY VILLAGE.
TO TAKE BACK
ALL OF OUR VILLAGES!
THE FIRE NATION
WILL REGRET THE DAY
THEY SET FOOT ON OUR LAND!
[CHEERING]
COME WITH US.
I CAN'T.
YOUR MISSION IS TO
TAKE BACK YOUR HOME.
OURS IS TO GET AANG
TO THE NORTH POLE.
THAT'S HIM,
ISN'T IT?
THE AVATAR.
KATARA, THANK YOU
FOR BRINGING MY
FATHER BACK TO ME.
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE HIM AGAIN.
I ONLY WISH
THERE WAS SOME WAY--
I KNOW.
MY MOTHER'S NECKLACE!
IT'S GONE!
♪