Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Katara, voice-over:
WHEN THE AVATAR DIES,
HE'S REINCARNATED
INTO THE NEXT NATION
IN THE CYCLE.
Aang: THAT'S AVATAR ROKU,
THE AVATAR BEFORE ME.
WHEN YOU ARE READY,
HE WILL REVEAL
HIMSELF TO YOU.
I LOST MY MOTHER
IN A FIRE NATION RAID.
THIS NECKLACE IS ALL I
HAVE LEFT OF HER.
THE WORLD HAS CHANGED
IN THE HUNDRED YEARS
YOU'VE BEEN GONE.
IT'S THE DUTY
OF THE AVATAR TO
RESTORE BALANCE
TO THE WORLD
BY DEFEATING
FIRE LORD OZAI.
SEND WORD TO
THE FIRE LORD IMMEDIATELY.
THE AVATAR
HAS RETURNED.
[SQUAWK]
[APPA GROWLING]
Katara: THOSE CLOUDS
LOOK SO SOFT, DON'T THEY?
LIKE YOU COULD
JUST JUMP DOWN
AND YOU'D LAND
IN A BIG, SOFT,
COTTONY HEAP.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
GIVE IT A TRY.
YOU'RE HILARIOUS.
I'LL TRY IT!
HA HA HA!
YEAH!
TURNS OUT, CLOUDS
ARE MADE OF WATER.
HEY, WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S LIKE A SCAR.
Sokka: LISTEN.
IT'S SO QUIET.
THERE'S NO LIFE
ANYWHERE.
AANG, ARE YOU OK?
FIRE NATION!
THOSE EVIL SAVAGES
MAKE ME SICK.
THEY HAVE
NO RESPECT FOR--
SHH.
WHAT, I'M NOT
ALLOWED TO BE ANGRY?
[SIGH]
WHY WOULD ANYONE DO THIS?
HOW COULD I LET THIS HAPPEN?
AANG, YOU DIDN'T
LET THIS HAPPEN.
IT HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH YOU.
YES, IT DOES.
IT'S THE AVATAR'S JOB
TO PROTECT NATURE,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DO MY JOB.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE GOING
TO THE NORTH POLE--
TO FIND YOU
A TEACHER.
YEAH. A WATERBENDING TEACHER.
BUT THERE'S NO ONE
WHO CAN TEACH ME HOW
TO BE THE AVATAR.
MONK GYATSU SAID THAT
AVATAR ROKU WOULD HELP ME.
THE AVATAR
BEFORE YOU?
HE DIED
OVER A HUNDRED
YEARS AGO.
HOW ARE YOU
SUPPOSED TO TALK
TO HIM?
I DON'T KNOW.
[PURRING]
UNCLE,
IT'S TIME TO LEAVE.
WHERE ARE YOU?
UNCLE IROH!
OVER HERE.
UNCLE?
WE NEED TO MOVE ON.
WE'RE CLOSING IN
ON THE AVATAR'S
TRAIL,
AND I DON'T
WANT TO LOSE HIM.
YOU LOOK TIRED,
PRINCE ZUKO.
WHY DON'T YOU JOIN ME
IN THESE HOT SPRINGS
AND SOAK AWAY
YOUR TROUBLES?
MY TROUBLES CANNOT
BE SOAKED AWAY.
IT'S TIME TO GO!
YOU SHOULD TAKE
YOUR TEACHER'S ADVICE
AND RELAX A LITTLE.
THE TEMPERATURE'S
JUST RIGHT.
I HEATED IT MYSELF.
ENOUGH. WE NEED
TO LEAVE NOW.
GET OUT
OF THE WATER!
VERY WELL.
ON SECOND THOUGHT,
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
ANOTHER FEW MINUTES?
BUT BE BACK
AT THE SHIP
IN HALF AN HOUR,
OR I'M LEAVING
WITHOUT YOU.
AHH.
Katara: HEY, AANG.
ARE YOU READY
TO BE CHEERED UP?
NO.
OW!
HEY, HOW IS THAT
CHEERING ME UP?
[CHUCKLING]
CHEERED ME UP.
OW!
YEAH, I PROBABLY
DESERVED THAT.
THESE ACORNS
ARE EVERYWHERE, AANG.
THAT MEANS THE FOREST
WILL GROW BACK.
EVERY ONE OF THESE
WILL BE A TALL
OAK TREE SOMEDAY,
AND ALL THE BIRDS
AND ANIMALS
THAT LIVED HERE
WILL COME BACK.
THANKS, KATARA.
[GASP]
Sokka: HEY,
WHO ARE YOU?
WHEN I SAW
THE FLYING BISON,
I THOUGHT
IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE,
BUT THOSE MARKINGS...
ARE YOU THE AVATAR,
CHILD?
MY VILLAGE
DESPERATELY NEEDS
YOUR HELP.
THIS YOUNG PERSON
IS THE AVATAR.
SO THE RUMORS
OF YOUR RETURN ARE TRUE.
IT IS THE GREATEST HONOR
OF A LIFETIME
TO BE IN YOUR PRESENCE.
NICE TO MEET YOU,
TOO.
SO, IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN HELP YOU WITH?
I'M NOT SURE.
OUR VILLAGE
IS IN CRISIS.
HE'S OUR ONLY HOPE.
FOR THE LAST FEW DAYS
AT SUNSET,
A SPIRIT MONSTER COMES
AND ATTACKS OUR VILLAGE.
HE IS HEI BAI,
THE BLACK AND WHITE SPIRIT.
WHY IS IT
ATTACKING YOU?
WE DO NOT KNOW.
BUT EACH
OF THE LAST 3 NIGHTS,
HE HAS ABDUCTED
ONE OF OUR OWN.
WE ARE ESPECIALLY
FEARFUL
BECAUSE THE WINTER
SOLSTICE DRAWS NEAR.
WHAT HAPPENS THEN?
AS THE SOLSTICE
APPROACHES,
THE NATURAL WORLD
AND THE SPIRIT WORLD
GROW CLOSER
AND CLOSER,
UNTIL THE LINE
BETWEEN THEM
IS BLURRED COMPLETELY.
HEI BAI IS ALREADY
CAUSING DEVASTATION
AND DESTRUCTION.
ONCE THE SOLSTICE
IS HERE,
THERE IS NO TELLING
WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
SO WHAT DO YOU
WANT ME TO DO EXACTLY?
WHO BETTER
TO RESOLVE A CRISIS
BETWEEN OUR WORLD
AND THE SPIRIT WORLD
THAN THE AVATAR
HIMSELF?
YOU ARE
THE GREAT BRIDGE
BETWEEN MAN
AND SPIRITS.
RIGHT. THAT'S ME.
HEY,
GREAT BRIDGE GUY.
CAN I TALK
TO YOU OVER HERE
FOR A SECOND?
AANG, YOU SEEM
A LITTLE UNSURE
ABOUT ALL THIS.
YEAH. THAT MIGHT BE
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING AT ALL
ABOUT THE SPIRIT
WORLD.
IT'S NOT LIKE
THERE'S SOMEONE TO
TEACH ME THIS STUFF.
SO, CAN YOU HELP
THESE PEOPLE?
I HAVE TO TRY,
DON'T I?
MAYBE WHATEVER
I HAVE TO DO
WILL JUST...
COME TO ME.
[PURRING]
I THINK YOU
CAN DO IT, AANG.
YEAH.
WE'RE ALL GONNA
GET EATEN BY
A SPIRIT MONSTER.
[SNORING]
[RUSTLING]
WHO'S THERE?
[SQUEAKING]
A MEADOW VOLE.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN.
YOU STARTLED ME,
LITTLE ONE.
[SIGH]
SEEMS I DOZED OFF AND MISSED
MY NEPHEW'S DEADLINE,
BUT IT WAS A VERY SWEET NAP.
[SQUEAKING]
[RUMBLING]
UHH!
HE'S A FIRE NATION
SOLDIER.
HE'S NO
ORDINARY SOLDIER.
THIS IS
THE FIRE LORD'S
BROTHER.
THE DRAGON
OF THE WEST--
THE ONCE GREAT
GENERAL IROH.
BUT NOW,
HE'S OUR PRISONER.
HELLO? SPIRIT?
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
THIS IS THE AVATAR SPEAKING.
I'M HERE TO TRY
TO HELP STUFF.
THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
WE CAN'T SIT HERE
AND COWER WHILE AANG
WAITS FOR SOME
MONSTER TO SHOW UP.
IF ANYONE CAN SAVE US,
HE CAN.
HE STILL SHOULDN'T
HAVE TO FACE THIS
ALONE.
THE SUN IS SET.
WHERE ARE YOU, HEI BAI?
WELL, SPIRIT, UH,
I HEREBY ASK YOU
TO PLEASE LEAVE
THIS VILLAGE IN PEACE.
OK. WELL, I GUESS
THAT'S SETTLED, THEN.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
YOU MUST BE
THE HEI BAI SPIRIT.
MY NAME IS--
[ROARS]
MY NAME IS AANG.
I'M THE AVATAR,
AND I WOULD LIKE TO HELP.
HEY, WAIT UP!
[ROARING]
UH...
THE AVATAR'S
METHODS ARE...
UNUSUAL.
IT DOESN'T SEEM
TOO INTERESTED
IN WHAT HE'S SAYING.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
GO HELP HIM.
NO. ONLY THE AVATAR
STANDS A CHANCE
AGAINST THE HEI BAI.
AANG WILL FIGURE OUT
THE RIGHT THING
TO DO, SOKKA.
PLEASE, WOULD YOU STOP
DESTROYING THINGS AND LISTEN?
I'M JUST TRYING
TO DO MY JOB
AS SPIRIT BRIDGE.
EXCUSE ME.
WOULD YOU PLEASE
TURN AROUND?
I COMMAND YOU
TO TURN AROUND NOW!
UHH!
THAT'S IT.
HE NEEDS HELP.
SOKKA! WAIT!
Leader:
IT'S NOT SAFE.
HEI BAI. OVER HERE!
SOKKA! GO BACK!
WE'LL FIGHT HIM
TOGETHER, AANG.
I DON'T WANT TO
FIGHT HIM UNLESS I--
SOKKA!
UNCLE.
UNCLE, WHERE ARE YOU?
SIR, MAYBE HE THOUGHT
YOU LEFT WITHOUT HIM.
SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT HERE.
THAT PILE OF ROCKS.
IT LOOKS LIKE
THERE'S BEEN
A LANDSLIDE, SIR.
LAND DOESN'T SLIDE UPHILL.
THOSE ROCKS
DIDN'T MOVE NATURALLY.
MY UNCLE'S BEEN CAPTURED
BY EARTHBENDERS.
[GASPING]
Sokka: AANG!
OVER HERE!
HELP!
HANG ON, SOKKA!
[GRUNTING]
AAH!
UHH!
SOKKA!
I'VE FAILED.
WHERE ARE YOU
TAKING ME?
WE'RE TAKING YOU
TO FACE JUSTICE.
RIGHT.
BUT WHERE,
SPECIFICALLY?
A PLACE YOU'RE
QUITE FAMILIAR WITH,
ACTUALLY.
YOU ONCE LAID SIEGE
TO IT FOR 600 DAYS,
BUT IT WOULD NOT
YIELD TO YOU.
AH, THE GREAT CITY
OF BA SING SE.
IT WAS GREATER
THAN YOU WERE,
APPARENTLY.
I ACKNOWLEDGE MY DEFEAT
AT BA SING SE.
AFTER 600 DAYS
AWAY FROM HOME,
MY MEN WERE TIRED,
AND I WAS TIRED.
[YAWN]
AND I'M STILL TIRED.
I'M SURE
THEY'LL BE BACK.
I KNOW.
YOU SHOULD
GET SOME REST.
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE OK.
YOUR BROTHER
IS IN GOOD HANDS.
I WOULD BE SHOCKED
IF THE AVATAR
RETURNED
WITHOUT HIM.
KATARA?
KATARA, I LOST HIM.
THE SUN IS RISING.
PERHAPS HE WILL
RETURN SOON.
WHAT? NO.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
GRR!
[GRUNTING]
I'M IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
UGH. YEP,
THAT'S UNCLE IROH.
Aang: I'LL FIGURE
THIS OUT, KATARA.
I PROMISE.
LIKE THEY SAID,
I'M THE BRIDGE
BETWEEN THE WORLDS,
RIGHT?
ALL I HAVE TO DO
IS FIGURE OUT
WHAT I HAVE TO DO,
BUT ONCE I DO THAT,
NO PROBLEM.
[GROWLING]
APPA. HEY, BUDDY.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
BUT I GUESS YOU
CAN'T SEE ME, EITHER.
[DULL ROAR]
IT'S OK, APPA.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M SURE THEY'RE
ON THEIR WAY BACK.
I BET THEY EVEN
FOUND YOU A BUNCH
OF MOON PEACHES,
FOR A TREAT.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
AVATAR ROKU,
HOW CAN I TALK TO YOU?
SOKKA?
[GROWLING]
THAT'S DEFINITELY NOT SOKKA.
UHH!
WHAT?
I CAN'T AIRBEND
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD.
[GROWLING]
YOU DON'T KNOW WHERE
SOKKA IS, DO YOU?
[WHIMPERING]
YOU'RE AVATAR ROKU'S
ANIMAL GUIDE,
LIKE APPA IS TO ME.
I NEED TO SAVE MY FRIEND,
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW.
IS THERE SOME WAY FOR ME
TO TALK TO ROKU?
I'LL BE BACK, KATARA.
TAKE ME TO ROKU.
[GASP]
OH.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
NOTHING.
ACTUALLY, THERE IS
A BIT OF A PROBLEM.
MY OLD JOINTS
ARE FEELING SORE
AND ACHY,
AND THESE SHACKLES
ARE TOO LOOSE.
TOO LOOSE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE CUFFS ARE LOOSE,
AND THEY JANGLE AROUND
AND BUMP MY WRISTS.
IT WOULD HELP ME
IF YOU WOULD TIGHTEN THEM
SO THEY WOULDN'T
SHAKE AROUND SO MUCH.
VERY WELL.
CORPORAL, TIGHTEN
THE PRISONER'S
HANDCUFFS.
AAH!
Aang: HEY!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
AAH!
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS JUST A STATUE
OF ROKU.
IS THAT WHAT ROKU
WANTS TO TALK TO ME ABOUT?
A COMET?
WHEN CAN I TALK TO HIM?
[GROWLING]
IT'S A CALENDAR,
AND THE LIGHT WILL REACH ROKU
ON THE SOLSTICE.
SO THAT'S WHEN I'LL BE
ABLE TO SPEAK TO ROKU?
[GROWLING]
BUT I CAN'T WAIT THAT LONG.
I NEED TO SAVE SOKKA NOW!
UGH! UHH!
HYAH!
HE IS TOO DANGEROUS,
CAPTAIN.
WE CAN'T
JUST CARRY HIM
TO THE CAPITAL.
WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING NOW.
I AGREE.
HE MUST BE DEALT WITH
IMMEDIATELY
AND SEVERELY.
PTOH!
Katara: IT'S NO USE, APPA.
I DON'T SEE THEM ANYWHERE.
OUR BEST HOPE IS TO GO BACK
TO THE VILLAGE AND WAIT.
[APPA GROWLS]
THE AVATAR.
WHOA.
AAH!
YOU'RE BACK!
WHERE'S SOKKA?
I'M NOT SURE.
Captain: THESE DANGEROUS HANDS
MUST BE CRUSHED.
[GRUNTING]
HYAH!
EXCELLENT FORM,
PRINCE ZUKO.
YOU TAUGHT ME WELL.
Captain:
SURRENDER YOURSELVES.
IT'S 5 AGAINST 2.
YOU'RE CLEARLY OUTNUMBERED.
UH, THAT'S TRUE,
BUT YOU ARE
CLEARLY OUTMATCHED.
HY...AH!
YAH!
HYAH! HYAH!
[GRUNTING]
HYAH!
UHH!
UHH! UHH!
YAH!
OH!
[SOLDIERS GROANING]
NOW, WOULD YOU PLEASE
PUT ON SOME CLOTHES?
[VOICES WHISPERING]
[CHIMING]
AAH!
AANG!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
RUN!
[ROARING]
YOU'RE THE SPIRIT
OF THIS FOREST.
NOW I UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE UPSET
AND ANGRY
BECAUSE YOUR HOME
WAS BURNED DOWN.
WHEN I SAW THE FOREST
HAD BURNED, I WAS SAD AND UPSET,
BUT MY FRIEND
GAVE ME HOPE
THAT THE FOREST
WOULD GROW BACK.
SOKKA!
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU WERE TRAPPED
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD
FOR 24 HOURS.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
LIKE I SERIOUSLY NEED
TO USE THE BATHROOM.
THANK YOU, AVATAR.
IF ONLY THERE WERE A WAY
TO REPAY YOU
FOR WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
YOU COULD GIVE US
SOME SUPPLIES
AND SOME MONEY.
SOKKA.
WHAT?
WE NEED STUFF.
IT WOULD BE AN HONOR
TO HELP YOU PREPARE
FOR YOUR JOURNEY.
I'M SO PROUD
OF YOU, AANG.
YOU FIGURED OUT WHAT TO DO
ALL ON YOUR OWN.
ACTUALLY, I DID HAVE
A LITTLE HELP.
AND THERE'S
SOMETHING ELSE.
WHAT IS IT?
I NEED TO TALK
TO ROKU,
AND I THINK
I FOUND A WAY
TO CONTACT
HIS SPIRIT.
THAT'S GREAT.
CREEPY,
BUT GREAT.
THERE'S A TEMPLE
ON A CRESCENT-SHAPED ISLAND,
AND IF I GO THERE
ON THE SOLSTICE,
I'LL BE ABLE
TO SPEAK WITH HIM.
BUT THE SOLSTICE
IS TOMORROW.
YEAH, AND THERE'S
ONE MORE PROBLEM.
THE ISLAND
IS IN THE FIRE NATION.
♪