Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR...
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Katara: WHEN THE AVATAR DIES,
HE'S REINCARNATED
INTO THE NEXT NATION
IN THE CYCLE.
BUT THERE'S NO ONE
WHO COULD TEACH ME
HOW TO BE THE AVATAR.
MONK GYATSU SAID THAT
AVATAR ROKU WOULD HELP ME.
Sokka: THE AVATAR BEFORE YOU?
HE DIED OVER 100 YEARS AGO.
HOW ARE YOU SUPPOSED TO
TALK TO HIM?
- THERE'S A TEMPLE
ON A CRESCENT-SHAPED ISLAND,
AND IF I GO THERE
ON THE SOLSTICE,
I'LL BE ABLE TO SPEAK
WITH HIM.
BUT THE SOLSTICE IS TOMORROW.
YEAH, AND THERE'S
ONE MORE PROBLEM.
THE ISLAND
IS IN THE FIRE NATION.
LET'S GO, APPA!
COME ON, BOY.
[GRUNTING]
LOOK, I'M SORRY,
BUT KATARA AND SOKKA
AREN'T COMING
TO THE FIRE NATION
WITH US.
IF THEY GOT HURT,
I'D NEVER FORGIVE
MYSELF.
SO GET YOUR BIG
BUTT OFF THE GROUND
AND LET'S GO!
UHH...
AAH!
Sokka:
I THINK HIS BIG BUTT
IS TRYING TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
Katara: PLEASE DON'T
GO, AANG.
THE WORLD CAN'T
AFFORD TO LOSE YOU
TO THE FIRE NATION.
NEITHER CAN I.
BUT I HAVE TO TALK
TO AVATAR ROKU
TO FIND OUT
WHAT MY VISION MEANS.
I NEED TO GET
TO THE FIRE TEMPLE
BEFORE THE SUN SETS
ON THE SOLSTICE.
THAT'S TODAY!
WE'RE NOT
LETTING YOU GO INTO
THE FIRE NATION, AANG.
AT LEAST NOT WITHOUT
YOUR FRIENDS.
WE GOT YOUR BACK.
EW!
IT'S A LONG JOURNEY
TO THE CRESCENT ISLAND.
YOU'LL HAVE TO FLY FAST
TO HAVE ANY CHANCE
OF MAKING IT
BEFORE SUNDOWN.
GOOD LUCK.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR--
GO!
[GRUNT]
AH.
HAVING TROUBLE
SLEEPING?
UH!
SEEN THE AVATAR LATELY?
COME ON, BOY.
WE'VE GOT A LONG WAY TO GO.
FASTER!
[GRUNT]
SAILING INTO
FIRE NATION WATERS.
OF ALL THE FOOLISH
THINGS YOU'VE DONE
IN YOUR 16 YEARS,
PRINCE ZUKO,
THIS IS THE MOST
FOOLISH.
I HAVE NO CHOICE, UNCLE.
HAVE YOU COMPLETELY
FORGOTTEN
THAT THE FIRE LORD
BANISHED YOU?
WHAT IF
YOU'RE CAUGHT?
I'M CHASING THE AVATAR.
MY FATHER WILL UNDERSTAND
WHY I'M RETURNING HOME.
YOU GIVE HIM
TOO MUCH CREDIT.
MY BROTHER IS NOT
THE UNDERSTANDING TYPE.
THERE THEY ARE.
HELMSMAN, FULL STEAM AHEAD.
AANG, WE GOT
TROUBLE.
YEAH, AND IT'S
GAINING FAST!
REALLY, PRINCE ZUKO,
COULDN'T YOU SHOOT
THEM DOWN
WITH SOMETHING
MORE FRAGRANT?
HUH!
ON MY MARK.
FIRE!
FIRE BALL!
I'M ON IT!
WE HAVE TO GET
OUT OF ZUKO'S
RANGE
BEFORE HE SHOOTS
ANOTHER HOT
STICKER AT US!
CAN'T YOU MAKE APPA
GO ANY FASTER?
YEAH, BUT THERE'S
JUST ONE LITTLE PROBLEM.
A BLOCKADE.
TECHNICALLY,
YOU ARE STILL
IN EARTH KINGDOM
WATERS.
TURN BACK NOW,
AND THEY CANNOT
ARREST YOU.
IF WE FLY NORTH,
WE CAN GO AROUND
THE FIRE NATION SHIPS
AND AVOID THE BLOCKADE.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
Katara: THERE'S NO TIME!
THIS IS EXACTLY WHY
I DIDN'T WANT YOU TO COME.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
WHY WE'RE HERE.
LET'S RUN THIS BLOCKADE.
APPA, YIP YIP!
[APPA GRUNTS]
HE'S NOT
TURNING AROUND.
PLEASE, PRINCE ZUKO.
IF THE FIRE NATION
CAPTURES YOU,
THERE IS NOTHING
I CAN DO.
DO NOT FOLLOW
THE AVATAR.
I'M SORRY, UNCLE.
RUN THE BLOCKADE!
Zhao: THE AVATAR...
AND THE BANISHED PRINCE.
THIS MUST BE
MY LUCKY DAY.
COMMANDER ZHAO,
WHAT ARE YOUR ORDERS?
SHOOT THE BISON
DOWN, CAPTAIN.
BUT THERE'S A FIRE NAVY
SHIP OUT THERE, SIR--
ONE OF OUR OWN.
WHAT IF IT'S HIT?
SO BE IT.
IT BELONGS
TO A TRAITOR.
IGNITE!
LAUNCH!
AAH!
APPA, ARE YOU OK?
[GRUNTS]
- PRINCE ZUKO,
THE ENGINES
ARE DAMAGED!
WE NEED TO STOP
AND MAKE REPAIRS!
DO NOT STOP THIS SHIP.
LAUNCH!
AAH!
[GRUNT]
SOKKA!
AAH!
OH!
READY.
FIRE!
AAH!
HUH!
AAH! OOH!
WE MADE IT!
WE GOT INTO
THE FIRE NATION.
GREAT.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THE AVATAR IS HEADED, SIR?
I'M NOT SURE,
BUT I BET A CERTAIN
BANISHED PRINCE
WILL KNOW.
WE'RE ON
A COLLISION COURSE!
WE CAN MAKE IT.
THE BOARDING PARTY
IS READY TO APPREHEND
PRINCE ZUKO, SIR.
WAIT.
CUT THE ENGINES
AND LET THEM
PASS.
SIR?
[APPA SNORING]
THERE IT IS--
THE ISLAND WHERE ROKU'S
DRAGON TOOK ME.
YOU DID IT, BUDDY.
NICE FLYING.
[SNORING]
OH, YOU MUST BE TIRED.
NO, I'M GOOD.
REFRESHED AND READY
TO FIGHT SOME FIREBENDERS.
I WAS TALKING TO APPA.
WELL, I WAS TALKING
TO MOMO.
Sokka: I DON'T SEE
ANY GUARDS.
Katara:
THE FIRE NATION
MUST HAVE ABANDONED
THE TEMPLE
WHEN AVATAR ROKU
DIED.
IT'S ALMOST SUNDOWN.
WE'D BETTER HURRY.
WAIT. I THINK
I HEARD SOMETHING.
WE ARE THE FIRE SAGES,
GUARDIANS OF THE TEMPLE
OF THE AVATAR.
GREAT. I AM THE AVATAR.
WE KNOW.
I'LL HOLD THEM OFF. RUN!
UH!
IF THE AVATAR
CONTACTS ROKU,
THERE'S NO TELLING
HOW POWERFUL
THE BOY WILL BECOME.
SPLIT UP AND FIND HIM.
FOLLOW ME!
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
NOPE.
WRONG WAY!
Fire sage: COME BACK!
I DON'T WANT TO FIGHT YOU.
I AM A FRIEND.
FIREBENDERS
AREN'T OUR FRIENDS.
I KNOW WHY
YOU'RE HERE, AVATAR.
YOU DO?
YES. YOU WISH TO SPEAK
TO AVATAR ROKU.
I CAN TAKE YOU
TO HIM.
HOW?
UH!
THIS WAY.
Zhao: FIND HIM!
TIME IS RUNNING OUT!
QUICKLY!
WHAT'S HE UP TO,
UNCLE?
WHY DIDN'T COMMANDER
ZHAO ARREST ME?
BECAUSE HE WANTS
TO FOLLOW YOU.
HE KNOWS
YOU'LL LEAD HIM
TO THE PRIZE
YOU'RE BOTH AFTER--
THE AVATAR.
IF ZHAO WANTS TO FOLLOW
OUR TRAIL OF SMOKE,
THEN THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I'LL LET HIM DO.
Fire sage:
AVATAR ROKU ONCE CALLED
THIS TEMPLE HIS HOME.
HE FORMED THESE SECRET
PASSAGES OUT OF THE MAGMA.
Aang: DID YOU KNOW
AVATAR ROKU?
NO, BUT MY GRANDFATHER
KNEW HIM.
MANY GENERATIONS
OF FIRE SAGES
GUARDED THIS TEMPLE
LONG BEFORE ME.
WE ALL HAVE
A STRONG SPIRITUAL
CONNECTION
TO THIS PLACE.
IS THAT HOW YOU KNEW
I WAS COMING?
A FEW WEEKS AGO,
AN AMAZING
THING OCCURRED.
THE STATUE
OF AVATAR ROKU--
ITS EYES
BEGAN TO GLOW.
Katara: THAT'S WHEN WE WERE
AT THE AIR TEMPLE.
AVATAR ROKU'S EYES
WERE GLOWING THERE, TOO.
AT THAT MOMENT,
WE KNEW YOU HAD
RETURNED TO THE WORLD.
IF THIS IS
THE AVATAR'S TEMPLE,
WHY DID THE SAGES ATTACK ME?
THINGS HAVE CHANGED.
IN THE PAST,
THE SAGES WERE LOYAL
ONLY TO THE AVATAR.
WHEN ROKU DIED, THE SAGES
EAGERLY AWAITED FOR THE NEXT
AVATAR TO RETURN,
BUT HE NEVER CAME.
THEY WERE WAITING FOR ME.
HEY, DON'T FEEL BAD.
YOU'RE ONLY 100 YEARS LATE.
THEY LOST HOPE
THAT THE AVATAR
WOULD EVER RETURN.
WHEN FIRE LORD SOZIN
BEGAN THE WAR,
MY GRANDFATHER
AND THE OTHER SAGES
WERE FORCED
TO FOLLOW HIM.
I NEVER WANTED
TO SERVE
THE FIRE LORD.
WHEN I LEARNED
YOU WERE COMING,
I KNEW I WOULD HAVE TO
BETRAY THE OTHER SAGES.
THANK YOU
FOR HELPING ME.
WE'LL FOLLOW THESE STAIRS
TO THE SANCTUARY.
ONCE YOU'RE INSIDE,
WAIT FOR THE LIGHT TO HIT
AVATAR ROKU'S STATUE.
ONLY THEN WILL YOU BE
ABLE TO SPEAK WITH HIM.
[GASP]
NO!
SHYU, WHAT'S WRONG?
THE SANCTUARY DOORS--
THEY'RE CLOSED.
CAN'T YOU JUST
OPEN THEM
WITH FIREBENDING,
LIKE YOU OPENED
THAT OTHER DOOR?
Shyu: NO. ONLY A FULLY
REALIZED AVATAR
IS POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO OPEN THIS DOOR ALONE.
OTHERWISE, THE SAGES MUST
OPEN THE DOORS TOGETHER
WITH 5 SIMULTANEOUS
FIRE BLASTS.
5 FIRE BLASTS, HUH?
[DING]
I THINK I CAN HELP YOU OUT.
Zuko: UNCLE,
KEEP HEADING NORTH.
ZHAO WILL FOLLOW
THE SMOKE TRAIL
WHILE I USE IT
AS A COVER.
HMMM.
Sokka:
THIS IS A LITTLE TRICK
I PICKED UP
FROM MY FATHER.
I SEAL THE LAMP OIL
INSIDE AN ANIMAL
SKIN CASING.
SHYU LIGHTS
THE OIL-SOAKED TWINE,
AND TA DA!
FAKE FIREBENDING.
YOU'RE REALLY
OUTDONE YOURSELF
THIS TIME, SOKKA.
THIS MIGHT
ACTUALLY WORK.
THE SAGES WILL HEAR
THE EXPLOSION,
SO AS SOON AS
THEY GO OFF,
YOU RUSH IN.
IT'S ALMOST SUNSET.
ARE YOU READY?
DEFINITELY.
OOH!
UH! UH!
THEY'RE STILL LOCKED!
IT DIDN'T WORK.
WHY WON'T IT OPEN?! UH!
AANG, STOP.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE
WE CAN DO.
I'M SORRY I PUT YOU
THROUGH ALL THIS
FOR NOTHING.
Sokka:
I DON'T GET IT.
THAT BLAST
LOOKED AS STRONG
AS ANY FIREBENDING
I'VE SEEN.
SOKKA,
YOU'RE A GENIUS!
WAIT. HOW IS SOKKA
A GENIUS?
HIS PLAN DIDN'T
EVEN WORK.
COME ON, AANG.
LET HER DREAM.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
SOKKA'S PLAN
DIDN'T WORK,
BUT IT LOOKS
LIKE IT DID.
DID THE DEFINITION
OF GENIUS CHANGE
IN THE LAST
HUNDRED YEARS?
Fire sage: COME QUICKLY!
THE AVATAR HAS ENTERED
THE SANCTUARY!
HOW DID HE GET IN?
I KNOW, BUT LOOK
AT THE SCORCH MARKS,
AND DOWN THERE.
HE'S INSIDE.
OPEN THE DOORS IMMEDIATELY
BEFORE HE CONTACTS
AVATAR ROKU.
HUH!
[SNEEZE]
IT'S THE AVATAR'S
LEMUR.
HE MUST HAVE CRAWLED
THROUGH THE PIPES.
WE'VE BEEN TRICKED!
[YOWLING]
AAH!
NOW, AANG.
AANG, NOW'S
YOUR CHANCE!
THE AVATAR'S
COMING WITH ME.
UH! UH!
UH!
CLOSE THE DOORS,
QUICKLY!
UH!
AAH!
GO!
HE MADE IT!
THE LIGHT HITS THE STATUE,
AND I TALK TO ROKU.
SO WHY ISN'T ANYTHING
HAPPENING?
HUH!
WHY ISN'T IT WORKING?
IT'S SEALED SHUT.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
THE LIGHT.
AVATAR ROKU DOESN'T
WANT US INSIDE.
Aang: WHY ISN'T
ANYTHING HAPPENING?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'M DOING.
ALL I KNOW IS AIRBENDING.
PLEASE, AVATAR ROKU,
TALK TO ME.
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU, AANG.
WHAT TOOK YOU
SO LONG?
Zuko: WHY DID YOU
HELP THE AVATAR?
BECAUSE IT WAS ONCE
THE SAGE'S DUTY.
IT IS STILL OUR DUTY.
[ONE PERSON CLAPPING]
WHAT A MOVING
AND HEARTFELT PERFORMANCE.
I'M CERTAIN
THE FIRE LORD WILL UNDERSTAND
WHEN YOU EXPLAIN WHY
YOU BETRAYED HIM.
COMMANDER ZHAO--
Zhao: AND, PRINCE ZUKO,
IT WAS A NOBLE EFFORT,
BUT YOUR LITTLE SMOKESCREEN
DIDN'T WORK.
TWO TRAITORS
IN ONE DAY.
THE FIRE LORD
WILL BE PLEASED.
YOU'RE TOO LATE,
ZHAO.
THE AVATAR'S
INSIDE,
AND THE DOORS
ARE SEALED.
NO MATTER.
SOONER OR LATER,
HE HAS TO COME OUT.
I HAVE SOMETHING
VERY IMPORTANT
TO TELL YOU, AANG.
THAT IS WHY, WHEN YOU WERE
IN THE SPIRIT WORLD,
I SENT MY DRAGON
TO FIND YOU.
IS IT ABOUT
THAT VISION--
THE ONE OF THE COMET?
YES.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
100 YEARS AGO,
FIRE LORD SOZIN
USED THAT COMET
TO BEGIN THE WAR.
HE AND HIS
FIREBENDING ARMY
HARNESSED ITS
INCREDIBLE POWER
AND DEALT A DEADLY
FIRST STRIKE
AGAINST THE OTHER
NATIONS.
SO THE COMET
MADE THEM STRONGER?
YES, STRONGER THAN YOU
COULD EVEN IMAGINE.
BUT THAT HAPPENED
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO.
WHAT DOES THE COMET
HAVE TO DO WITH
THE WAR NOW?
LISTEN CAREFULLY.
SOZIN'S COMET WILL RETURN
BY THE END OF THIS SUMMER,
AND FIRE LORD OZAI
WILL USE ITS POWER
TO FINISH THE WAR
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
AAH!
IF HE SUCCEEDS,
EVEN THE AVATAR
WON'T BE ABLE TO RESTORE
BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
AANG, YOU MUST
DEFEAT THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET
ARRIVES.
BUT I HAVEN'T EVEN
STARTED LEARNING
WATERBENDING,
NOT TO MENTION
EARTH AND FIRE.
MASTERING THE ELEMENTS
TAKES YEARS OF DISCIPLINE
AND PRACTICE,
BUT IF THE WORLD
IS TO SURVIVE,
YOU MUST DO IT
BY SUMMER'S END.
Zhao: WHEN THOSE DOORS OPEN,
UNLEASH ALL YOUR FIREPOWER.
HOW'S AANG GONNA
MAKE IT OUT OF THIS?
HOW ARE WE GONNA
WHAT IF I CAN'T MASTER
ALL THE ELEMENTS
IN TIME?
WHAT IF I FAIL?
I KNOW YOU CAN DO IT,
AANG,
FOR YOU HAVE DONE IT BEFORE.
THE SOLSTICE IS ENDING.
WE MUST GO OUR SEPARATE
WAYS FOR NOW.
BUT I WON'T BE ABLE
TO COME BACK
TO THE TEMPLE.
WHAT IF I HAVE
QUESTIONS?
HOW WILL I TALK
TO YOU?
I AM A PART OF YOU.
WHEN YOU NEED TO TALK
TO ME AGAIN,
YOU WILL FIND A WAY.
A GREAT DANGER AWAITS YOU
AT THE TEMPLE.
I CAN HELP YOU FACE
THE THREAT,
BUT ONLY IF YOU
ARE READY.
I'M READY.
Zhao: READY...
NO! AANG!
FIRE!
AVATAR ROKU!
UH!
OH!
AVATAR ROKU IS
GOING TO DESTROY
THE TEMPLE.
WE HAVE TO GET
OUT OF HERE!
NOT WITHOUT AANG!
HUH!
WE GOT YOUR BACK.
THANKS. WHERE'S SHYU?
I DON'T KNOW.
UH!
[GASPS]
NO PRINCE, NO AVATAR.
APPARENTLY THE ONLY THING
I DO HAVE
IS 5 TRAITORS.
BUT, COMMANDER,
ONLY SHYU HELPED
THE AVATAR.
SAVE YOUR STORIES
FOR THE FIRE LORD.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
YOU ARE ALL GUILTY.
TAKE THEM TO THE
PRISON HOLD!
♪