Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED, AND MY BROTHER
AND I DISCOVERED THE NEW
AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF!
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Aang: YOU'RE A WATERBENDER!
WELL, NOT YET.
IF WE GO
TO THE NORTH POLE,
YOU CAN MASTER
WATERBENDING.
WE CAN LEARN IT
TOGETHER.
I LOST MY MOTHER
IN A FIRE NATION RAID.
THIS NECKLACE IS ALL
I HAVE LEFT OF HER.
Roku: AANG, YOU MUST
DEFEAT THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET ARRIVES.
BUT I HAVEN'T EVEN
STARTED LEARNING
WATERBENDING,
NOT TO MENTION
EARTH AND FIRE.
MASTERING THE ELEMENTS
TAKES YEARS OF DISCIPLINE
AND PRACTICE,
BUT IF THE WORLD
IS TO SURVIVE,
YOU MUST DO IT
BY SUMMER'S END.
[PANTING]
Sokka: WOULD YOU SIT DOWN?!
IF WE HIT A BUMP,
YOU'LL GO FLYING OFF!
WHAT'S BUGGING YOU ANYWAY?
IT'S WHAT AVATAR
ROKU SAID.
I'M SUPPOSED TO MASTER
ALL 4 ELEMENTS
BEFORE THAT COMET ARRIVES.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
YOU PRETTY MUCH
MASTERED AIRBENDING, AND THAT
ONLY TOOK YOU 112 YEARS.
I'M SURE YOU CAN MASTER 3 MORE
ELEMENTS BY NEXT SUMMER.
I HAVEN'T EVEN
STARTED WATERBENDING,
AND WE'RE STILL WEEKS AWAY
FROM THE NORTH POLE.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?!
CALM DOWN.
IT'S GONNA
BE OK.
IF YOU WANT,
I CAN TRY
AND TEACH YOU
SOME OF THE STUFF
I KNOW.
YOU'D DO THAT?
WE'LL NEED TO FIND
A GOOD SOURCE
OF WATER FIRST.
MAYBE WE CAN FIND A PUDDLE
FOR YOU TO SPLASH IN.
NICE PUDDLE.
[SNORTING]
[SCREECHES]
Aang: YEAH!
DON'T START
WITHOUT ME, BOY!
REMEMBER THE REASON
WE'RE HERE.
OH, RIGHT.
TIME TO PRACTICE
WATERBENDING.
GREAT. SO, WHAT AM
I SUPPOSED TO DO?
YOU COULD
CLEAN THE GUNK
OUT OF
APPA'S TOES.
SO, WHILE YOU GUYS ARE
PLAYING IN THE WATER,
I'M SUPPOSED TO
BE HARD AT WORK
PICKING MUD OUT OF
A GIANT BISON'S FEET?
MUD AND BUGS.
OK.
[GRUNTING]
WHOA! WHOA!
OOF!
SOMEONE'S CHANGING
OUR COURSE.
WHAT'S THE MEANING
OF THIS MUTINY?
NO ONE TOLD YOU
TO CHANGE COURSE.
ACTUALLY,
SOMEONE DID.
I ASSURE YOU,
IT IS A MATTER OF
UTMOST IMPORTANCE,
PRINCE ZUKO.
IS IT SOMETHING TO
DO WITH THE AVATAR?
EVEN MORE URGENT.
IT SEEMS I--
I'VE LOST
MY LOTUS TILE.
LOTUS TILE?
FOR MY PAI SHO
GAME.
MOST PEOPLE THINK
THE LOTUS TILE
INSIGNIFICANT.
BUT IT IS ESSENTIAL FOR
THE UNUSUAL STRATEGY
THAT I EMPLOY.
YOU'VE CHANGED OUR COURSE
FOR A STUPID LOTUS TILE?
SEE, YOU,
LIKE MOST PEOPLE,
UNDERESTIMATE
ITS VALUE.
JUST GIVE ME 10 MINUTES
TO CHECK THE MERCHANTS
AT THIS PORT OF CALL.
HOPEFULLY, THEY'LL HAVE
THE LOTUS TILE IN STOCK
AND I CAN GET ON
WITH MY LIFE.
[BREATHING DEEPLY]
I'M LUCKY TO HAVE SUCH
AN UNDERSTANDING NEPHEW.
[SIGHS]
YEAH, DON'T
GET TOO HAPPY.
YOU'VE GOT TO DO ME NEXT.
[SIGHS]
THIS IS A PRETTY
BASIC MOVE,
BUT IT STILL TOOK ME
MONTHS TO PERFECT.
SO, DON'T BE
FRUSTRATED
IF YOU DON'T GET
IT RIGHT AWAY.
JUST PUSH AND PULL
THE WATER LIKE THIS.
THE KEY IS
GETTING THE WRIST
MOVEMENT RIGHT.
LIKE THIS?
THAT'S ALMOST RIGHT.
IF YOU KEEP
PRACTICING,
I'M SURE
EVENTUALLY--
HEY, I'M BENDING
IT ALREADY!
WOW! I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU GOT THAT SO QUICKLY.
IT TOOK ME TWO MONTHS
TO LEARN THAT MOVE.
WELL, YOU HAD
TO FIGURE IT OUT
ALL ON YOUR OWN.
I'M LUCKY ENOUGH TO
HAVE A GREAT TEACHER.
THANKS.
SO, WHAT'S NEXT?
THIS IS A MORE
DIFFICULT MOVE.
I CALL IT
STREAMING THE WATER.
IT'S HARDER
THAN IT LOOKS, SO DON'T BE
DISAPPOINTED IF...
NICE WORK.
THOUGH THE OVER-THE-HEAD
FLAIR WAS UNNECESSARY.
SORRY.
WELL, DON'T STOP NOW.
KEEP 'EM COMING.
WELL, I KIND OF KNOW
THIS ONE OTHER MOVE,
BUT IT'S
PRETTY HARD.
I HAVEN'T EVEN TOTALLY
FIGURED IT OUT YET.
THE IDEA IS TO CREATE
A BIG, POWERFUL WAVE.
[GRUNTS]
SO, LIKE THIS?
AANG!
LOOKS LIKE I GOT
THE HANG OF THAT MOVE.
WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
THAT'S ENOUGH
PRACTICING FOR TODAY.
YEAH, I'LL SAY!
YOU JUST PRACTICED
OUR SUPPLIES
DOWN THE RIVER.
UH, SORRY.
I'M SURE WE CAN
FIND SOME WAY
TO REPLACE
ALL THIS STUFF.
MY LIFE WAS HARD ENOUGH
WHEN YOU WERE
JUST AN AIRBENDER.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Man: PLEASE,
PUT ME DOWN!
Vender: SEE THE WONDER
IN THIS BAG!
WHO'S BRAVE ENOUGH
TO LOOK INTO THIS BAG?!
WOW!
WE'VE GOT EXACTLY
3 COPPER PIECES LEFT
FROM THE MONEY THAT
KING BUMI GAVE US.
LET'S SPEND IT WISELY.
UH, MAKE THAT TWO
COPPER PIECES, SOKKA.
I COULDN'T SAY NO
TO THIS WHISTLE.
[AIR HISSES]
IT DOESN'T EVEN WORK.
[SQUEALS]
SEE? EVEN MOMO THINKS
IT'S A PIECE OF JUNK.
NO OFFENSE, AANG,
BUT I'LL HOLD
THE MONEY FROM NOW ON.
Man: EARTH NATION!
FIRE NATION!
WATER NATION.
SO LONG AS BARGAINS
ARE YOUR INCLINATION,
YOU'RE WELCOME HERE!
DON'T BE SHY.
COME ON BY!
OH, YOU THERE!
I CAN SEE FROM
YOUR CLOTHING
THAT YOU'RE WORLD
TRAVELING TYPES.
PERHAPS I CAN
INTEREST YOU
IN SOME EXOTIC CURIOS?
SURE!
WHAT ARE CURIOS?
I'M NOT ENTIRELY SURE,
BUT WE GOT 'EM.
[GASPS]
HUH?
Man: I'VE NEVER SEEN SUCH
A FINE SPECIMEN OF LEMUR.
THAT BEAST WOULD
FETCH ME A HEFTY SUM
IF YOU'D BE INTERESTED
IN BARTERING.
[SQUAWKS]
[HISSES]
MOMO'S NOT
FOR SALE.
LOOK AT THIS, AANG!
IT'S A WATERBENDING SCROLL.
CHECK OUT THESE
CRAZY MOVES.
WHERE DID YOU GET
A WATERBENDING SCROLL?
LET'S JUST SAY
I GOT IT UP NORTH
AT A MOST
REASONABLE PRICE--
FREE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
SEA-LOVING TRADERS
WITH SUSPICIOUSLY
ACQUIRED MERCHANDISE
AND PET REPTILE BIRDS?
YOU GUYS ARE PIRATES!
WE PREFER TO THINK
OF OURSELVES AS
HIGH-RISK TRADERS.
SO, HOW MUCH FOR
THE TRADED SCROLL?
I'VE ALREADY
GOT A BUYER--
A NOBLEMAN
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM--
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
YOU KIDS HAVE
200 GOLD PIECES
ON YOU RIGHT NOW.
I KNOW HOW TO
DEAL WITH THESE
GUYS, KATARA.
PIRATES LOVE
TO HAGGLE.
WATCH AND LEARN.
WHAT SAY YE TO
THE PRICE OF...
ONE COPPER PIECE?
HA HA HA HA!
THE PRICE IS
200 GOLD PIECES.
I DON'T HAGGLE
ON ITEMS THIS RARE.
OK, TWO COPPER PIECES.
IT'S NOT AS AMUSING
THE SECOND TIME, BOY.
AANG, CAN WE
GET OUT OF HERE?
I FEEL LIKE WE'RE
GETTING WEIRD LOOKS.
AYE! WE BE
CASTING OFF NOW!
WHAT WAS THAT ALL
ABOUT, KATARA?
YEAH, I WAS JUST STARTING
TO BROWSE THROUGH
THEIR BOOMERANG COLLECTION.
I'LL JUST FEEL
A LOT BETTER
ONCE WE GET
AWAY FROM HERE.
HEY, YOU!
GET BACK HERE!
WELL, WELL.
LOOK WHO'S COME
TO THEIR SENSES.
TOLD YOU THE HAGGLING
WOULD PAY OFF.
[GROWLING]
THERE THEY ARE!
GET 'EM!
NOBODY'S GOING NOWHERE!
[LAUGHING]
I DON'T THINK
THESE PIRATES
ARE HERE TO
TRADE WITH US.
GET BACK HERE!
YOU LITTLE--
COME ON!
THIS WAY.
LET'S CUT 'EM OFF!
WHOA!
OOF!
OH! OH!
[SCREAMING]
MY CABBAGES!
THIS PLACE IS WORSE
THAN OMASHU!
[GROANING]
AHA!
[SHUDDERS]
I HOPE THAT
LEMUR OF YOURS
HAS 9 LIVES.
NOW, WHO GETS TO TASTE
THE STEEL OF MY
BLADE FIRST?
NO, THANKS.
HAA!
[SCREAMS]
GRAB ON TIGHT!
AANG, I
THOUGHT WE WERE
RUNNING AWAY FROM
THE PIRATES.
JUST HANG ON.
Both: WHOA!
OW!
WHOA!
I USED TO KIND OF
LOOK UP TO PIRATES,
BUT THOSE GUYS
ARE TERRIBLE.
I KNOW.
THAT'S WHY I TOOK THIS.
NO WAY!
ISN'T IT GREAT?!
NO WONDER THEY WERE
TRYING TO HACK US UP.
YOU STOLE THEIR
WATERBENDING SCROLL.
I PREFER TO
THINK OF IT AS
HIGH-RISK TRADING.
HA HA HA.
GOOD ONE, KATARA.
SOKKA, WHERE TO YOU
THINK THEY GOT IT?
THEY STOLE IT FROM
A WATERBENDER.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
YOU PUT ALL OF OUR
LIVES IN DANGER
JUST SO YOU
COULD LEARN
SOME STUPID,
FANCY SPLASHES.
THESE ARE REAL
WATERBENDING FORMS.
YOU KNOW HOW
CRUCIAL IT IS
FOR AANG TO LEARN
WATERBENDING.
[SIGHS]
WHATEVER.
WELL, WHAT'S
DONE IS DONE.
WE HAVE IT.
WE MIGHT AS WELL
LEARN FROM IT.
I'VE CHECKED ALL
THE SHOPS ON THIS PIER.
NOT A LOTUS TILE IN
THE ENTIRE MARKETPLACE.
IT'S GOOD TO
KNOW THIS TRIP
WAS A COMPLETE
WASTE OF TIME
FOR EVERYONE!
QUITE THE CONTRARY.
I ALWAYS SAY THE ONLY
THING BETTER THAN
FINDING SOMETHING
YOU ARE LOOKING FOR
IS FINDING SOMETHING
YOU WEREN'T LOOKING FOR AT A
GREAT BARGAIN.
YOU BOUGHT
A SUNGI HORN?
FOR MUSIC NIGHT
ON THE SHIP.
NOW, IF WE ONLY
HAD SOME WOODWINDS.
OH, THIS PLACE
LOOKS PROMISING.
OH, THAT IS HANDSOME!
WOULDN'T IT LOOK
MAGNIFICENT IN THE GALLEY?
WE LOST THE WATER
TRIBE GIRL
AND THE LITTLE
BALD MONK
SHE WAS
TRAVELING WITH.
THIS MONK, DID HE HAVE
AN ARROW ON HIS HEAD?
[IMITATES
MONKEY]
I JUST WANT TO TRY
THIS ONE MOVE FIRST,
AND THEN IT'S
ALL YOURS.
HERE, HOLD IT
OPEN FOR ME.
THE SINGLE WATER WHIP.
LOOKS DOABLE.
OW!
HA HA HA!
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
I'M SORRY, BUT
YOU DESERVED THAT.
YOU'VE BEEN DUPED.
SHE'S ONLY
INTERESTED IN
TEACHING HERSELF.
AANG WILL GET HIS TURN
ONCE I FIGURE OUT
THE WATER WHIP.
[SCREECHES]
UGH! WHY CAN'T I GET
THIS STUPID MOVE?!
YOU'LL GET IT.
YOU'VE JUST GOTTA
SHIFT YOUR WEIGHT
THROUGH THE STANCES.
THERE. SEE?
THE KEY TO BENDING IS--
WILL YOU PLEASE
SHUT YOUR AIR HOLE!
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
YOUR INFINITE WISDOM
GETS A LITTLE
OLD SOMETIMES!
WHY DON'T WE JUST
THROW THE SCROLL AWAY
SINCE YOU'RE SO
NATURALLY GIFTED?!
WHAT?!
OH, MY GOSH, AANG.
I AM SO SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT CAME OVER ME.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT WON'T
HAPPEN AGAIN.
HERE, THIS IS YOURS.
I DON'T WANT TO HAVE
ANYTHING TO DO
WITH IT ANYMORE.
IT'S OK, KATARA.
WHAT ABOUT MOMO?
HE'S THE REAL VICTIM HERE.
I'M SORRY, MOMO.
AND WHAT ABOUT ME?
THERE WAS THAT
TIME YOU--
NO MORE APOLOGIES.
SHOULDN'T WE STOP
TO SEARCH THE WOODS?
WE DON'T NEED
TO STOP.
THEY STOLE
A WATERBENDING
SCROLL, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
THEN THEY'LL
BE ON THE WATER.
[PURRS]
SHH.
MOMO, GO BACK
TO SLEEP.
[COOS]
SHH!
[GRUNTING]
SHOOT!
COME ON, WATER!
WORK WITH ME HERE!
OK, WHAT IF I--OW!
[DISTANT YELLING]
OK, KATARA,
SHIFT YOUR WEIGHT
THROUGH THE STANCES.
UGH!
[SCRAPING]
[GASPS]
AH! NO!
LET GO OF ME!
[GRUNTS]
I'LL SAVE YOU
FROM THE PIRATES.
TELL ME WHERE HE IS,
AND I WON'T HURT YOU
OR YOUR BROTHER.
GO JUMP IN THE RIVER!
TRY TO UNDERSTAND,
I NEED TO CAPTURE HIM
TO RESTORE
SOMETHING I'VE LOST--
MY HONOR.
PERHAPS IN EXCHANGE,
I CAN RESTORE
SOMETHING YOU'VE LOST.
MY MOTHER'S NECKLACE.
HOW DID YOU GET THAT?!
I DIDN'T STEAL IT
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE WONDERING.
TELL ME WHERE HE IS.
NO!
ENOUGH OF THIS
NECKLACE GARBAGE.
YOU PROMISED THE SCROLL.
I WONDER HOW MUCH
MONEY THIS IS WORTH.
[GASPS]
NO!
A LOT, APPARENTLY.
NOW, YOU HELP ME
FIND WHAT I WANT,
YOU'LL GET THIS BACK,
AND EVERYONE
GOES HOME HAPPY.
SEARCH THE WOODS FOR THE BOY
AND MEET BACK HERE.
FINE.
[GROANING]
HUH?
WHERE DID SHE GO?
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
[YAWNS]
WHAT'S WRONG?
SHE TOOK THE SCROLL.
SHE'S OBSESSED
WITH THAT THING.
IT'S JUST A MATTER
OF TIME BEFORE SHE GETS US
ALL IN DEEP-- WHOA!
[SCREAMS]
[YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
I'VE GOT HIM.
COME ON!
OH, WHAT? I'M NOT GOOD
ENOUGH TO KIDNAP?
AAGH!
NICE WORK.
[STRAINING]
AANG, THIS IS
ALL MY FAULT.
NO, KATARA,
IT ISN'T.
YEAH,
IT KIND OF IS.
GIVE ME THE BOY.
YOU GIVE US
THE SCROLL.
YOU'RE REALLY GONNA
HAND OVER THE AVATAR
FOR A STUPID PIECE
OF PARCHMENT?
DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
HE'S TRYING TO TURN
US AGAINST EACH OTHER.
YOUR FRIEND
IS THE AVATAR?
SURE IS.
AND I'LL BET HE'LL
FETCH A LOT MORE
ON THE BLACK MARKET
THAN THAT FANCY SCROLL.
SHUT YOUR MOUTH,
YOU WATER TRIBE
PEASANT!
YEAH, SOKKA, YOU REALLY
SHOULD SHUT YOUR MOUTH.
I'M JUST SAYING,
IT'S BAD
BUSINESS SENSE.
JUST IMAGINE HOW
MUCH THE FIRE LORD
WOULD PAY FOR
THE AVATAR.
YOU GUYS WOULD BE
SET FOR LIFE.
KEEP THE SCROLL.
WE CAN BUY 100
WITH THE REWARD
WE'LL GET FOR THE KID.
YOU'LL REGRET BREAKING
A DEAL WITH ME.
[GROWLS]
[SCREAMING]
[YELLING]
THANKS, MOMO.
I OWE YOU A BUSHEL
OF APPLES.
[COUGHING]
[GRUNTS]
HEY!
[SQUAWKS]
[SQUAWK]
[SWORDS CLANGING]
AAH!
AANG, ARE YOU THERE?
I'M OVER HERE!
FOLLOW MY VOICE.
WHERE? I CAN'T FIND YOU!
I'M RIGHT HERE!
UH, NEVER MIND.
I'LL FIND YOU!
RUN!
KATARA, YOU'RE OK.
HELP ME GET THIS BOAT
BACK IN THE WATER
SO WE CAN GET
OUT OF HERE.
[ALL STRAINING]
WE NEED A TEAM
OF RHINOS
TO BUDGE
THIS SHIP.
A TEAM OF RHINOS...
OR TWO WATERBENDERS.
Katara: EVERYBODY IN!
ARE YOU SO
BUSY FIGHTING
YOU CANNOT SEE
YOUR OWN SHIP
HAS SET SAIL?
WE HAVE NO
TIME FOR YOUR
PROVERBS, UNCLE.
IT'S NO PROVERB.
BLEEDING HOG MONKEYS!
HA HA HA HA!
[LAUGHTER]
HEY, THAT'S
MY BOAT!
MAYBE IT SHOULD
BE A PROVERB.
COME ON, UNCLE.
SOKKA, CAN'T YOU MAKE
IT GO ANY FASTER?
I DON'T KNOW HOW.
THIS THING WASN'T MADE
BY THE WATER TRIBE.
[GRUNTING]
WHOA!
OOF!
HEY! YOU DID
THE WATER WHIP.
I COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
WILL YOU TWO QUIT
CONGRATULATING EACH OTHER
AND HELP ME OUT?
[SQUEAKING]
[SCREAMING]
THAT'S GOOD.
WAH!
HAH!
[SCREAMING]
AANG, LOOK!
OH, NO!
[AIR HISSING]
AAH! OH!
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MIND?
THIS IS NO TIME
FOR FLUTE PRACTICE!
WE CAN STOP THE BOAT.
AANG, TOGETHER,
PUSH AND PULL THE WATER.
IT'S WORKING.
IT'S SLOWING DOWN.
WE'RE DOING IT!
BUT WE HAVE
ANOTHER PROBLEM.
WHOA!
JUMP!
[SCREAMING]
Aang: I KNEW A BISON WHISTLE
WOULD COME IN HANDY.
THANKS, APPA.
Sokka: YEAH,
WE OWE YOU ONE.
[GRUNTS]
MY BOAT!
[PANTING]
[CHUCKLES]
PRINCE ZUKO,
YOU'RE REALLY GOING TO
GET A KICK OUT OF THIS.
THAT LOTUS TILE WAS IN MY
SLEEVE THE WHOLE TIME!
[GROWLING]
[GRUNTS]
Katara: AANG,
I STILL OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY.
YOU WERE JUST SO GOOD
AT WATERBENDING
WITHOUT REALLY TRYING.
I GOT SO COMPETITIVE
THAT I PUT US
ALL IN DANGER.
I'M SORRY.
THAT'S OK,
KATARA.
BESIDES, WHO NEEDS THAT
STUPID SCROLL ANYWAY?
IS THAT REALLY
HOW YOU FEEL?
THE SCROLL!
FIRST, WHAT DID YOU LEARN?
STEALING IS WRONG.
UNLESS IT'S
FROM PIRATES.
Aang: HA HA HA!
GOOD ONE, KATARA.
♪