Katara: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
- UNH!
- BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
- I'M EMBARRASSED
TO BE RELATED TO YOU!
EVER SINCE MOM DIED,
I'VE BEEN DOING ALL
THE WORK AROUND CAMP
WHILE YOU'VE BEEN OFF
PLAYING SOLDIER!
[SHUDDERING]
KATARA...
WARRIORS,
AWAY FROM THE ENEMY.
SOKKA, YOU'RE
MAKING A MISTAKE.
NO, I'M KEEPING
MY PROMISE TO DAD.
I'M PROTECTING YOU
FROM THREATS LIKE HIM.
I LOST MY MOTHER
IN A FIRE NATION RAID.
THIS NECKLACE IS
ALL I HAVE LEFT OF HER.
- IT'S NOT ENOUGH, IS IT?
- NO.
JUST PUSH AND PULL
THE WATER--LIKE THIS.
HEY, I'M BENDING IT ALREADY!
UNH!
HUH.
[SCREECHING]
[ANIMALS GRUNTING]
- WHERE'S MOMO?
[SCREECH]
HANG ON, MOMO!
UHH!
[ANIMALS GRUNTING]
ALL RIGHT, YOU TOO.
THIS IS GOING
TO TAKE FOREVER.
THAT WORKS.
[GRUNTING]
THESE ARE FIRE
NATION TRAPS.
YOU CAN TELL FROM
THE METALWORK.
WE'D BETTER PACK UP
CAMP AND GET MOVING.
UH-UH! NO FLYING
THIS TIME.
WHAT? WHY
WOULDN'T WE FLY?
THINK ABOUT IT.
SOMEHOW PRINCE ZUKO
AND THE FIRE NATION
KEEP FINDING US.
IT'S BECAUSE THEY SPOT APPA,
HE'S JUST TOO NOTICEABLE.
WHAT? APPA'S NOT
TOO NOTICEABLE.
HE'S A GIGANTIC FLUFFY MONSTER
WITH AN ARROW ON HIS HEAD!
IT'S KIND OF HARD
TO MISS HIM.
[GROWLS]
SOKKA'S JUST JEALOUS BECAUSE
HE DOESN'T HAVE AN ARROW.
I KNOW YOU ALL
WANT TO FLY,
BUT MY
INSTINCTS TELL ME WE SHOULD PLAY
IT SAFE THIS TIME AND WALK.
WHO MADE YOU THE BOSS?
I'M NOT THE BOSS,
I'M THE LEADER.
YOU'RE THE LEADER?
BUT YOUR VOICE
STILL CRACKS.
I'M THE OLDEST,
AND I'M A WARRIOR!
SO I'M THE LEADER.
IF ANYONE'S THE LEADER,
IT'S AANG.
I MEAN, HE IS THE AVATAR.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
HE'S JUST A GOOFY KID.
HE'S RIGHT.
WHY DO BOYS ALWAYS THINK
SOMEONE HAS TO BE THE LEADER?
I BET YOU WOULDN'T BE SO BOSSY
IF YOU KISSED A GIRL.
I'VE KISSED A GIRL!
YOU JUST HAVEN'T
MET HER.
WHO? GRAN-GRAN?
I'VE MET GRAN-GRAN.
NO, BESIDES
GRAN-GRAN.
LOOK, MY INSTINCTS
TELL ME
WE HAVE A BETTER
CHANCE OF SLIPPING
THROUGH ON FOOT,
AND A LEADER HAS
TO TRUST HIS INSTINCTS.
OK, WE'LL TRY
IT YOUR WAY,
O WISE LEADER.
WHO KNOWS?
WALKING MIGHT BE FUN.
WALKING STINKS!
HOW DID PEOPLE GO ANYWHERE
WITHOUT A FLYING BISON?
I DON'T KNOW, AANG.
WHY DON'T YOU ASK
SOKKA'S INSTINCTS?
THEY SEEM TO KNOW
EVERYTHING.
Sokka: HA HA,
VERY FUNNY.
I'M TIRED OF
CARRYING THIS PACK.
YOU KNOW WHO YOU SHOULD ASK
TO CARRY IT FOR A WHILE?
SOKKA'S INSTINCTS!
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
HEY, SOKKA'S INSTINCTS,
WOULD YOU MIND--
OK, OK, I GET IT!
LOOK, GUYS,
I'M TIRED, TOO.
BUT THE IMPORTANT THING IS THAT
WE'RE SAFE FROM THE FIRE NATION.
RUN!
HUH!
WE'RE CUT OFF!
SOKKA, YOUR SHIRT!
AAH!
IF YOU LET US PASS,
WE PROMISE NOT TO HURT YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
BLUFFING.
YOU, PROMISE
NOT TO HURT US?
UNH.
UHH...
NICE WORK, SOKKA.
HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
UH...INSTINCT?
LOOK!
UHH!
UNH!
DOWN YOU GO.
UHH!
THEY'RE
IN THE TREES!
HA HA HA!
HAH!
UNH!
HEY, HE WAS MINE.
GOTTA BE QUICKER NEXT TIME.
UNH!
UHH.
MAN!
HEY.
HI.
YOU JUST TOOK OUT
A WHOLE ARMY ALMOST
SINGLE-HANDED.
- ARMY?!
THERE WERE ONLY,
LIKE, 20 GUYS.
- MY NAME IS JET,
AND THESE ARE
MY FREEDOM FIGHTERS.
SNEERS, LONGSHOT,
SMELLERBEE,
THE DUKE,
AND PIPSQUEAK.
PIPSQUEAK,
THAT'S A FUNNY NAME.
[SNIFFS]
YOU THINK
MY NAME IS FUNNY?
IT'S HILARIOUS!
[LAUGHING]
UNH!
UM, THANKS FOR
SAVING US, JET.
WE'RE LUCKY
YOU WERE THERE.
I SHOULD BE
THANKING YOU.
WE WERE WAITING TO AMBUSH
THOSE SOLDIERS ALL MORNING.
WE JUST NEEDED
THE RIGHT DISTRACTION.
AND THEN YOU GUYS
STUMBLED IN.
WE WERE RELYING
ON INSTINCTS.
Jet: YOU'LL GET YOURSELF
KILLED DOING THAT.
[SNIFFING]
HEY, JET, THESE BARRELS
ARE FILLED WITH BLASTING JELLY.
THAT'S
A GREAT SCORE.
AND THESE BOXES ARE
FILLED WITH JELLIED CANDY.
ALSO GOOD.
LET'S NOT GET
THOSE MIXED UP.
WE'LL TAKE THE STUFF
BACK TO THE HIDEOUT.
YOU GUYS HAVE
A HIDEOUT?
- YOU WANT TO SEE IT?
- YES, WE WANT TO SEE IT!
Jet: WE'RE HERE.
WHERE?
THERE'S NOTHING HERE.
HOLD THIS.
WHY? WHAT'S THIS DO?
AAH!
- AANG?
- I'LL GET UP ON MY OWN.
GRAB HOLD OF ME,
KATARA.
NICE PLACE YOU GOT!
IT'S BEAUTIFUL UP HERE.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL,
AND MORE IMPORTANTLY,
THE FIRE NATION
CAN'T FIND US.
THEY WOULD LOVE
TO FIND YOU,
WOULDN'T THEY, JET?
IT'S NOT GOING
TO HAPPEN, SMELLERBEE.
Katara: WHY DOES THE FIRE
NATION WANT TO FIND YOU?
Jet: I GUESS YOU
COULD SAY
I'VE BEEN CAUSING THEM
A LITTLE TROUBLE.
SEE, THEY TOOK
OVER A NEARBY
EARTH KINGDOM TOWN
A FEW YEARS BACK.
WE'VE BEEN AMBUSHING
THEIR TROOPS,
CUTTING OFF THEIR
SUPPLY LINES,
AND DOING ANYTHING WE CAN
TO MESS WITH THEM.
ONE DAY, WE'LL DRIVE
THE FIRE NATION
OUT OF HERE
FOR GOOD,
AND FREE THAT TOWN.
THAT'S SO BRAVE.
YEAH, NOTHING'S BRAVER
THAN A GUY IN A TREE HOUSE.
DON'T PAY ANY ATTENTION
TO MY BROTHER.
NO PROBLEM.
HE PROBABLY
HAD A ROUGH DAY.
SO, YOU ALL LIVE HERE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LONGSHOT OVER THERE,
HIS TOWN GOT BURNED DOWN
BY THE FIRE NATION.
AND WE FOUND THE DUKE
TRYING TO STEAL OUR FOOD.
I DON'T THINK HE EVER
REALLY HAD A HOME.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
THE FIRE NATION
KILLED MY PARENTS.
I WAS ONLY 8 YEARS OLD.
THAT DAY CHANGED
ME FOREVER.
SOKKA AND I LOST OUR MOTHER
TO THE FIRE NATION.
I'M SO SORRY, KATARA.
[BIRDS CAWING]
[APPA GROWLING]
Jet: TODAY,
WE STRUCK ANOTHER BLOW
AGAINST THE FIRE NATION SWINE.
[CHEERING]
I GOT A SPECIAL JOY FROM
THE LOOK ON ONE SOLDIER'S FACE,
WHEN THE DUKE
DROPPED DOWN ON HIS HELMET
AND RODE HIM
LIKE A WILD HOG-MONKEY!
[CHEERING]
NOW, THE FIRE NATION
THINKS THEY DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT A COUPLE OF KIDS
HIDING IN THE TREES.
MAYBE THEY'RE RIGHT.
[BOOING]
OR MAYBE, THEY'RE DEAD WRONG.
[CHEERING]
HEY, JET,
NICE SPEECH.
THANKS.
BY THE WAY,
I WAS REALLY IMPRESSED
WITH YOU AND AANG.
THAT WAS SOME GREAT BENDING
I SAW OUT THERE TODAY.
WELL, HE'S GREAT.
HE'S THE AVATAR.
I COULD USE SOME
MORE TRAINING.
AVATAR, HUH? VERY NICE.
THANKS, JET.
SO I MIGHT KNOW A WAY
THAT YOU AND AANG
CAN HELP IN OUR STRUGGLE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE HAVE TO LEAVE TONIGHT.
SOKKA,
YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
I NEEDED YOU
ON AN IMPORTANT
MISSION TOMORROW.
WHAT MISSION?
[BIRD CALL]
[ANSWERING BIRD CALL]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
SHH. IT AMPLIFIES
VIBRATIONS.
GOOD TRICK.
NOTHING YET.
WAIT, YES!
SOMEONE'S APPROACHING.
HOW MANY?
I THINK THERE'S
JUST ONE.
[BIRD CALL]
GOOD WORK, SOKKA.
READY YOUR WEAPON.
WAIT! FALSE ALARM.
HE'S JUST
AN OLD MAN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN OUR WOODS, YOU LEECH?
PLEASE, SIR,
I'M JUST A TRAVELER.
UHH!
OHH!
UNH!
UHH!
DO YOU LIKE
DESTROYING TOWNS?
DESTROYING FAMILIES?
DO YOU?!
OH, PLEASE, LET ME GO.
HAVE MERCY.
DOES THE FIRE NATION
LET PEOPLE GO?
HAVE MERCY?
UHH!
JET, HE'S JUST
AN OLD MAN!
HE'S FIRE NATION!
SEARCH HIM!
BUT HE'S NOT
HURTING ANYONE.
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
THAT THE FIRE NATION
KILLED YOUR MOTHER?
REMEMBER WHY YOU FIGHT!
WE GOT HIS STUFF, JET.
THIS DOESN'T
FEEL RIGHT.
IT'S WHAT HAS TO BE DONE.
NOW LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
COME ON, SOKKA!
[LAUGHING]
- SOKKA, LOOK WHAT
THE DUKE GAVE ME.
[HISSES]
OW, QUIT IT!
HEY, SOKKA.
IS JET BACK?
YEAH, HE'S BACK.
BUT WE'RE LEAVING.
WHAT?
BUT I MADE HIM THIS HAT.
YOUR BOYFRIEND JET'S A THUG.
WHAT?!
NO, HE'S NOT.
HE'S MESSED UP, KATARA.
Aang: HE'S NOT
MESSED UP. HE'S JUST GOT
A DIFFERENT WAY OF LIFE.
A REALLY FUN
WAY OF LIFE.
HE BEAT
AND ROBBED
A HARMLESS
OLD MAN.
I WANT TO HEAR
JET'S SIDE OF THE STORY.
SOKKA, YOU TOLD
THEM WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT YOU DIDN'T MENTION
THAT THE GUY WAS FIRE NATION?
NO, HE CONVENIENTLY
LEFT THAT PART OUT.
FINE, BUT
EVEN IF HE WAS
FIRE NATION,
HE WAS A HARMLESS
CIVILIAN.
HE WAS AN ASSASSIN, SOKKA.
SEE? THERE'S A COMPARTMENT
FOR POISON IN THE KNIFE.
HE WAS SENT TO ELIMINATE ME.
YOU HELPED SAVE MY LIFE, SOKKA.
I KNEW THERE
WAS AN EXPLANATION.
I DIDN'T SEE
ANY KNIFE.
THAT'S BECAUSE
HE WAS CONCEALING IT.
SEE, SOKKA?
I'M SURE YOU JUST
DIDN'T NOTICE THE KNIFE.
THERE WAS
NO KNIFE!
I'M GOING BACK
TO THE HUT
AND PACKING
MY THINGS.
TELL ME YOU GUYS
AREN'T LEAVING YET.
I REALLY NEED YOUR HELP.
WHAT CAN WE DO?
THE FIRE NATION IS PLANNING
ON BURNING DOWN OUR FOREST.
IF YOU BOTH USE WATERBENDING
TO FILL THE RESERVOIR,
WE COULD FIGHT THE FIRES.
BUT IF YOU LEAVE NOW,
THEY'LL DESTROY
THE WHOLE VALLEY.
WE CAN'T LEAVE NOW
WITH THE FIRE NATION
ABOUT TO BURN DOWN A FOREST!
I'M SORRY, KATARA.
JET'S VERY SMOOTH,
BUT WE CAN'T TRUST HIM.
YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK?
YOU'RE JEALOUS THAT
HE'S A BETTER WARRIOR
AND A BETTER LEADER.
KATARA, I'M NOT
JEALOUS OF JET.
IT'S JUST THAT
MY INSTINCTS--
WELL, MY INSTINCTS TELL ME
WE NEED TO STAY HERE
A LITTLE LONGER AND HELP JET.
COME ON, AANG.
SORRY, SOKKA.
[SNORING]
Jet: LET'S GO.
HUH?
NOW LISTEN. YOU'RE NOT TO BLOW
THE DAM UNTIL I GIVE THE SIGNAL.
IF THE RESERVOIR ISN'T FULL,
THE FIRE NATION TROOPS
COULD SURVIVE.
BUT WHAT ABOUT
THE PEOPLE IN THE TOWN?
WON'T THEY GET
WIPED OUT, TOO?
LOOK, DUKE,
THAT'S THE PRICE
OF RIDDING THIS AREA
OF THE FIRE NATION.
NOW DON'T BLOW THE DAM
UNTIL I GIVE THE SIGNAL.
GOT IT?
[RUSTLING]
OW!
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING, PONYTAIL?
Jet: SOKKA.
I'M GLAD YOU DECIDED
TO JOIN US.
I HEARD YOUR PLAN TO DESTROY
THE EARTH KINGDOM TOWN.
OUR PLAN IS TO
RID THE VALLEY OF
THE FIRE NATION.
THERE ARE PEOPLE
LIVING THERE, JET,
MOTHERS AND FATHERS
AND CHILDREN.
WE CAN'T WIN WITHOUT
MAKING SOME SACRIFICES.
YOU LIED TO AANG
AND KATARA ABOUT
THE FOREST FIRE.
BECAUSE THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE DEMANDS OF WAR.
NOT LIKE YOU AND I DO.
I DO UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE'S NOTHING YOU WON'T DO
TO GET WHAT YOU WANT.
I WAS HOPING YOU'D
HAVE AN OPEN MIND.
BUT I CAN SEE YOU'VE
MADE YOUR CHOICE.
I CAN'T LET YOU WARN
KATARA AND AANG.
TAKE HIM FOR A WALK.
A LONG WALK.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS!
CHEER UP, SOKKA.
WE'RE GOING TO WIN
A GREAT VICTORY
AGAINST THE FIRE
NATION TODAY.
Katara: JET,
I'M SORRY ABOUT HOW
SOKKA'S BEEN ACTING.
NO WORRIES.
HE ALREADY
APOLOGIZED.
REALLY?
SOKKA APOLOGIZED?
YEAH, I WAS
SURPRISED, TOO.
I GOT THE SENSE
THAT MAYBE YOU
TALKED TO HIM
OR SOMETHING.
YEAH, I DID.
I GUESS SOMETHING YOU
SAID GOT THROUGH TO HIM.
ANYHOW, HE WENT OUT
ON A SCOUTING MISSION
WITH PIPSQUEAK
AND SMELLERBEE.
I'M GLAD HE COOLED OFF.
HE'S SO STUBBORN
SOMETIMES.
UHH!
ALL RIGHT,
WE'RE HERE.
UNDERGROUND WATER'S TRYING
TO ESCAPE FROM THESE VENTS.
I NEED YOU GUYS
TO HELP IT ALONG.
I'VE NEVER USED BENDING
ON WATER I CAN'T SEE.
I DON'T KNOW...
KATARA,
YOU CAN DO THIS.
WHAT ABOUT ME?
I KNOW THE AVATAR
CAN DO THIS.
Jet: YES! GOOD JOB.
THIS RIVER EMPTIES
INTO THE RESERVOIR.
A FEW MORE GEYSERS
AND IT WILL BE FULL.
LOOK, THERE'S
ANOTHER STEAM VENT.
OK, YOU TWO KEEP IT UP,
I'LL GO CHECK ON THINGS
AT THE RESERVOIR.
Katara: WHEN WE'RE DONE,
WE'LL MEET YOU OVER THERE.
ACTUALLY, PROBABLY
BETTER IF YOU MEET ME
BACK AT THE HIDEOUT
WHEN YOU'RE DONE.
I BET THAT'S ENOUGH.
AND I'M NOT JUST
SAYING THAT TO BE LAZY.
LET'S CATCH UP WITH JET
AT THE RESERVOIR.
I THOUGHT WE AGREED TO MEET
JET BACK AT THE HIDEOUT.
WELL, WE FINISHED EARLY.
I'M SURE HE'LL BE
HAPPY TO SEE US.
COME ON,
MOVE ALONG!
HOW CAN YOU STAND
BY AND DO NOTHING
WHILE JET WIPES OUT
A WHOLE TOWN?
HEY, LISTEN, SOKKA,
JET'S A GREAT LEADER.
WE FOLLOW WHAT HE SAYS,
AND THINGS ALWAYS TURN OUT OK.
IF THAT'S HOW JET LEADS,
THEN HE'S GOT
A LOT TO LEARN!
HEY!
UNH!
WHILE YOU TWO
ARE UP THERE, YOU MIGHT WANT TO
PRACTICE YOUR KNOT WORK.
HEY, SMELLERBEE.
YOU GOING TO EAT
YOUR LICHEE NUTS?
OOH.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
HEY, THOSE ARE
THE RED BARRELS
HE GOT FROM THE FIRE NATION.
WHY WOULD THEY NEED
BLASTING JELLY?
BECAUSE JET'S GOING
TO BLOW UP THE DAM.
WHAT? NO, THAT WOULD
DESTROY THE TOWN.
JET WOULDN'T DO THAT.
I'VE GOT TO STOP HIM!
UNH!
YES, I WOULD.
JET, WHY?
KATARA, YOU WOULD, TOO,
IF YOU JUST STOP TO THINK.
THINK ABOUT WHAT
THE FIRE NATION
DID TO YOUR MOTHER.
WE CAN'T LET THEM DO THAT
TO ANYONE ELSE EVER AGAIN.
THIS ISN'T THE ANSWER.
I WANT YOU TO
UNDERSTAND ME, KATARA.
I THOUGHT YOUR BROTHER
WOULD UNDERSTAND, BUT--
WHERE'S SOKKA?
KATARA.
UNH!
I NEED TO GET
TO THE DAM.
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE
WITHOUT YOUR GLIDER.
UNH! UHH! UNH!
I'M NOT GOING
TO FIGHT YOU, JET.
YOU'LL HAVE TO IF YOU
WANT YOUR GLIDER BACK.
HAH!
UNH!
AAH!
OHH...
UNH!
WHY, JET?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I TRUSTED YOU.
YOU LIED TO ME!
YOU'RE SICK,
AND I TRUSTED YOU!
[BIRD CALL]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE TOO LATE.
NO!
UNH!
SOKKA'S STILL OUT THERE.
HE'S OUR ONLY CHANCE.
COME ON, SOKKA.
I'M SORRY I
EVER DOUBTED YOU.
PLEASE...
NO.
SOKKA DIDN'T MAKE
IT IN TIME.
ALL THOSE PEOPLE.
JET, YOU MONSTER!
THIS WAS
A VICTORY, KATARA.
REMEMBER THAT.
THE FIRE NATION
IS GONE, AND THIS VALLEY
WILL BE SAFE.
Sokka: IT WILL BE SAFE, WITHOUT
YOU.
SOKKA!
I WARNED THE VILLAGERS
OF YOUR PLAN,
JUST IN TIME.
WHAT?!
AT FIRST, THEY DIDN'T
BELIEVE ME.
THE FIRE NATION SOLDIERS
ASSUMED I WAS A SPY.
BUT ONE MAN
VOUCHED FOR ME,
THE OLD MAN YOU ATTACKED.
HE URGED THEM TO TRUST ME,
AND WE GOT EVERYONE OUT IN TIME.
MRS. PRETTY!
SOKKA, YOU FOOL! WE COULD HAVE
FREED THIS VALLEY!
WHO WOULD BE FREE?
EVERYONE WOULD BE DEAD.
YOU TRAITOR!
NO, JET.
YOU BECAME THE TRAITOR
WHEN YOU STOPPED
PROTECTING INNOCENT PEOPLE.
KATARA, PLEASE,
HELP ME.
GOOD-BYE, JET.
YIP, YIP.
[APPA RUMBLING]
Aang: WE THOUGHT YOU
WERE GOING TO THE DAM.
HOW COME YOU WENT
TO THE TOWN INSTEAD?
LET ME GUESS.
YOUR INSTINCTS
TOLD YOU.
HEY, SOMETIMES
THEY'RE RIGHT.
UM, SOKKA?
YOU KNOW WE'RE GOING
THE WRONG WAY, RIGHT?
AND SOMETIMES
THEY'RE WRONG.
[APPA RUMBLING]
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]
♪