Katara: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: UNH!
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
THE WORLD HAS CHANGED IN
THE 100 YEARS YOU'VE BEEN GONE.
YOUR MISSION IS TO TAKE BACK
YOUR HOME.
OURS IS TO GET AANG
TO THE NORTH POLE.
- SOZIN'S COMET WILL RETURN BY
THE END OF THIS SUMMER.
YOU MUST DEFEAT THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET ARRIVES.
I HAVEN'T EVEN STARTED
WATER BENDING,
AND WE'RE STILL WEEKS AWAY
FROM THE NORTH POLE.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
- IF YOU WANT, I CAN TRY AND
TEACH YOU SOME OF THE STUFF I
KNOW.
HEY, I'M BENDING IT ALREADY.
[GRUNTING]
UM, AREN'T YOU
FORGETTING THE TARP?
RIGHT. GOT IT.
SOKKA, YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO PUT THE TARP
ON TOP OF THE TENT.
YOU KNOW, SO WE DON'T
GET RAINED ON?
ORDINARILY YOU'D BE RIGHT,
BUT SEEING HOW
IT'S THE DRY SEASON,
YOU'RE NOT.
BESIDES, THAT TARP MAKES
A PRETTY WARM BLANKET.
BUT WHAT IF
IT DOES RAIN?
WHAT IF IT DOESN'T?
THEN I WOULD HAVE PUT
THE TARP UP FOR NOTHING.
UH! YOU'RE
INFURIATING.
KATARA, WHY DON'T YOU
WORRY ABOUT GATHERING
THE FIREWOOD?
BECAUSE THAT KINDLING'S
LOOKING PRETTY SORRY.
WELL, IF YOU DON'T LIKE
MY FIREWOOD--
UH!
FINE BY ME!
IF YOU'RE NOT
GONNA DO YOUR JOB--
UH!
OK, I GOT THE GRUB
IF YOU GUYS GOT THE--
HEY, WHERE'S
THE CAMPFIRE,
AND WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE TENT?
WHY DON'T YOU ASK
MISS KNOW IT ALL,
QUEEN OF THE TWIGS?
OH, YEAH? WELL,
YOU'RE MR. LAZY BUM,
KING OF THE...
TENTS!
[CHUCKLING]
OK. LISTEN, GUYS.
HARSH WORDS
WON'T SOLVE PROBLEMS.
ACTION WILL.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
SWITCH JOBS?
SOUNDS GOOD.
WHATEVER.
YOU SEE THAT?
SETTLING FEUDS
AND MAKING PEACE--
ALL IN A DAY'S WORK
FOR THE AVATAR.
[YOWLING]
COME ON, MOMO.
THAT'S FAIR.
APPA'S GOT
5 STOMACHS.
[CHATTERING]
THERE IT IS, GUYS--
THE GREAT DIVIDE.
WOW. I COULD JUST
STARE AT IT FOREVER.
OK. I'VE
SEEN ENOUGH.
HOW CAN YOU NOT
BE FASCINATED, SOKKA?
THIS IS THE LARGEST CANYON
IN THE ENTIRE WORLD.
THEN I'M SURE WE'LL BE
ABLE TO SEE IT VERY CLEARLY
FROM THE AIR WHILE
WE FLY AWAY.
- HEY, IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR THE CANYON GUIDE,
I WAS HERE FIRST.
OOH. CANYON GUIDE.
SOUNDS INFORMATIVE.
BELIEVE ME,
HE'S MORE THAN
A TOUR GUIDE.
HE'S AN EARTHBENDER, AND THE
ONLY WAY IN AND OUT OF THE
CANYON
IS WITH HIS HELP.
AND HE'S TAKING
MY TRIBE ACROSS NEXT.
CALM DOWN.
WE KNOW YOU'RE NEXT.
YOU WOULDN'T BE CALM
IF THE FIRE NATION
DESTROYED YOUR HOME
AND FORCED YOU TO FLEE.
MY WHOLE TRIBE HAS TO
WALK THOUSANDS OF MILES
TO THE CAPITAL
CITY OF BA SING SE.
YOU'RE A REFUGEE.
HUH. TELL ME SOMETHING
I DON'T KNOW.
IS THAT YOUR TRIBE?
IT MOST CERTAINLY
IS NOT.
THAT'S THE ZHANG TRIBE,
A BUNCH OF LOWLIFE
THIEVES.
THEY'VE BEEN THE ENEMIES OF MY
TRIBE FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
[WHISTLES]
HEY, ZHANGS!
I'M SAVING A SPOT
FOR MY TRIBE,
SO DON'T EVEN THINK
OF STEALING IT.
WHERE ARE THE REST
OF THE GAN JIN?
STILL TIDYING UP
THEIR CAMPSITE?
YES, BUT THEY SENT ME
AHEAD OF THEM
TO HOLD A SPOT.
I DIDN'T KNOW
THE CANYON GUIDE
TOOK RESERVATIONS.
HUH! OF COURSE HE DIDN'T.
THAT'S THE IGNORANCE
I'D EXPECT
FROM A MESSY ZHANG,
SO UNORGANIZED
AND ILL-PREPARED
FOR A JOURNEY.
[MEN SHOUTING]
[CHATTERING]
UHH!
SORRY ABOUT THE WAIT,
YOUNGSTERS.
WHO'S READY TO CROSS
THIS HERE CANYON?
UH, ONE OF THEM,
I THINK.
I WAS HERE FIRST.
MY PARTY'S ON THEIR WAY.
I CAN'T GUIDE PEOPLE
WHO AREN'T HERE.
GUESS YOU GUYS WILL HAVE
TO MAKE THE TRIP TOMORROW.
WAIT! HERE THEY COME.
YOU'RE NOT SERIOUSLY
GONNA CAVE IN
TO THESE SPOILED
GAN JINS.
I MEAN,
WE'RE REFUGEES, TOO,
AND WE'VE GOT SICK
PEOPLE THAT NEED
SHELTER.
I, UH, WELL...
WE'VE GOT OLD PEOPLE
WHO ARE WEARY
FROM TRAVELING.
SICK PEOPLE GET
PRIORITY OVER OLD PEOPLE.
MAYBE YOU ZHANGS WOULDN'T
HAVE SO MANY SICK PEOPLE
IF YOU WEREN'T
SUCH SLOBS.
IF YOU GAN JINS
WEREN'T SO CLEAN,
MAYBE YOU WOULDN'T
LIVE TO BE SO OLD.
Gan Jin: I COULD SMELL
YOUR STINK...
WELL, AANG,
READY TO PUT
YOUR PEACEMAKING
SKILLS TO THE TEST?
I-I DON'T KNOW.
A FIGHT OVER CHORES
IS ONE THING.
THESE PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
FEUDING FOR A HUNDRED YEARS.
EVERYONE LISTEN UP!
THIS IS THE AVATAR,
AND IF YOU GIVE HIM
A CHANCE,
I'M SURE HE CAN COME UP
WITH A COMPROMISE
THAT WILL MAKE
EVERYONE HAPPY.
UH, YOU COULD SHARE
THE EARTHBENDER
AND TRAVEL TOGETHER?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
WE'D RATHER BE TAKEN
BY THE FIRE NATION
THAN TRAVEL WITH THOSE
STINKING THIEVES.
WE WOULDN'T TRAVEL
WITH YOU POMPOUS FOOLS
ANYWAY.
[ALL ARGUING]
ALL RIGHT,
HERE'S THE DEAL!
YOU'RE ALL GOING
DOWN TOGETHER, AND APPA HERE
WILL FLY YOUR SICK
AND ELDERLY ACROSS.
DOES THAT SEEM FAIR?
SORRY, APPA. YOU'LL HAVE TO
DO THIS ON YOUR OWN.
- AANG, THIS FEUDING TRIBE
STUFF IS SERIOUS BUSINESS.
ARE YOU SURE IT'S
A GOOD IDEA GETTING
INVOLVED IN THIS?
TO TELL THE TRUTH,
I'M NOT SURE,
BUT WHEN HAVE I
EVER BEEN?
HE'S THE AVATAR,
SOKKA.
MAKING PEACE
BETWEEN PEOPLE
IS HIS JOB.
HIS JOB'S GONNA MAKE US
CROSS THIS WHOLE THING
ON FOOT, ISN'T IT?
- OK, NOW COMES
THE BAD NEWS.
NO FOOD ALLOWED
IN THE CANYON.
IT ATTRACTS
DANGEROUS PREDATORS.
NO FOOD?
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
OH, YOU BABIES CAN GO
A DAY WITHOUT FOOD.
WOULD YOU RATHER BE
HUNGRY OR DEAD?
NOW, WE'RE HEADING DOWN
IN 10 MINUTES.
ALL FOOD BETTER BE
IN YOUR GUT
OR IN THE GARBAGE!
APPA'S GONNA TAKE
GOOD CARE OF YOU
TILL WE GET THERE.
SEE YOU ON THE OTHER
SIDE, BUDDY.
YIP YIP!
[GRUNT]
HUH!
Aang: NICE BENDING.
THE JOB'S MUCH MORE
THAN BENDING, KID.
FOLKS WANT
INFORMATION.
MANY OF YOU ARE
PROBABLY WONDERING
HOW CANYONS ARE FORMED.
EXPERTS TELL US
THIS CANYON WAS MOST LIKELY
CARVED INTO THE GROUND
BY EARTH SPIRITS,
WHO WERE ANGRY
AT LOCAL FARMERS
FOR NOT OFFERING THEM
A PROPER SACRIFICE.
[GASP]
[RUMBLING]
[SCREAMING]
UH! HA HA!
GUESS THE SPIRITS
ARE STILL ANGRY.
HOPE YOU ALL
BROUGHT SACRIFICES.
Guide: OK. EVERYONE
STAND CLEAR OF THE WALL.
UH! UH!
WHY DID YOU
DO THAT?
THESE PEOPLE ARE FLEEING
THE FIRE NATION,
AREN'T THEY?
I'VE GOT TO MAKE SURE
WE CAN'T BE FOLLOWED.
WE'LL BE SAFE NOW.
UH!
AH!
WE'VE GOT
TO HELP HIM! UH!
AAH!
[COUGH]
OK, NOW WE'VE GOT TO
HELP ME!
AAH!
HAH!
WHAT WAS THAT?
CANYON CRAWLER.
OH. AND THERE'S SURE
TO BE MORE.
YOUR ARMS--
THEY'RE BROKEN.
WITHOUT MY ARMS,
I GOT NO BENDING.
IN OTHER WORDS...
WE'RE TRAPPED
IN THIS CANYON.
I THOUGHT THE WHOLE POINT
OF DITCHING OUR FOOD
WAS SO WE WOULDN'T
HAVE TO DEAL WITH THINGS
LIKE CANYON CRAWLERS.
IT'S THE ZHANGS.
THEY TOOK FOOD DOWN HERE
EVEN AFTER THE GUIDE
TOLD THEM NOT TO.
WHAT? IF THERE'S ANYONE WHO
CAN'T GO WITHOUT FOOD
FOR A DAY,
IT'S THESE PAMPERED
GAN JINS.
Gan Jin: I HOPE
YOU'RE HAPPY.
WE'RE STUCK
IN THIS CANYON
WITH NO WAY OUT.
WHY DON'T YOU THANK
YOURSELF, FOOD-HIDER?
LOOK, STICKING TOGETHER
IS THE ONLY WAY TO--
I'M NOT WALKING
ANOTHER STEP
WITH THE LIKES OF THEM.
NOW THERE'S
SOMETHING
WE CAN AGREE ON.
ANY IDEAS?
NO BENDING. WE NEED TO GET
OUT OF THIS CANYON.
I WON'T DIE DOWN HERE.
I WON'T BECOME PART OF
THE FOOD CHAIN.
SEE? WE'RE GOING
TO BECOME PART
OF THE FOOD CHAIN
BECAUSE OF YOU.
SURE. UNJUSTLY BLAME
THE ZHANGS, LIKE YOU
ALWAYS DO.
GLADLY.
Aang: ENOUGH!
I THOUGHT I COULD
HELP YOU GUYS GET ALONG,
BUT I GUESS THAT'S
NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
WE SHOULD SPLIT UP--
GAN JINS ON THIS SIDE
AND ZHANGS ON THAT SIDE.
WE'LL TRAVEL
IN TWO SEPARATE LINES.
SOKKA, YOU GO
WITH THE ZHANGS,
AND, KATARA, YOU GO
WITH THE GAN JINS.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND OUT
WHY THEY HATE EACH OTHER
SO MUCH.
SO YOU GUYS AREN'T
GONNA PUT UP
YOUR TARPS?
WHAT FOR?
IT'S THE DRY SEASON.
EXACTLY!
BESIDES, WE LIKE TO USE
THE TARP AS A BLANKET.
FINALLY SOMEONE
GETS IT.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
IT'LL RAIN?
NO, BUT YOU CAN NEVER
BE TOO CAREFUL, RIGHT?
[GASP]
WOULD YOU CARE FOR
SOME BREAD, KATARA?
SO IT WAS YOU GUYS
WHO HAD FOOD.
OH, COME NOW. DO YOU REALLY
THINK THAT TRIBE OF THIEVES
ISN'T SMUGGLING FOOD?
WHY SHOULD MY PEOPLE
GO HUNGRY
WHEN THE SNEAKY ZHANGS
ARE STUFFING THEIR FACES?
WELL, I GUESS IT'S OK
IF EVERYONE'S DOING IT.
SO WHY DOES YOUR TRIBE
HATE THE ZHANGS SO MUCH?
YOU SEEM LIKE
A SMART GIRL, KATARA.
I BET YOU WOULD ENJOY
HEARING SOME HISTORY.
Gan Jin: THE PATRIARCH
OF OUR TRIBE, GHIN WAI,
WAS AN EARTHBENDER WARRIOR
WHO WAS ASSIGNED
AN IMPORTANT DUTY:
TRANSPORTING
OUR SACRED ORB
FROM THE GREAT EASTERN GATE
TO THE GREAT WESTERN GATE.
TAKING THE ORB
FROM THE EAST TO THE WEST
REPRESENTS THE SUN'S
RISING AND SETTING.
IT WAS OUR TRIBE'S
ANCIENT REDEMPTION RITUAL.
BUT AS HE APPROACHED
THE GATE,
GHIN WAI WAS ATTACKED
BY ONE OF THE ZHANGS--
A VERMIN NAMED WAI GHIN
WHO LOOKED AT THE ORB
WITH ENVY.
THAT COWARD WAI GHIN
KNOCKED GHIN WAI TO THE GROUND
AND STOLE OUR SACRED ORB.
OUR PEOPLE HAVE NEVER
FORGOTTEN.
YOU CAN NEVER TRUST
A ZHANG.
CARE FOR SOME MEAT?
WOULD I?
I KNOW WHAT YOU MUST
BE THINKING.
WE'RE HORRIBLE FOR
ENDANGERING EVERYBODY
BY BRINGING FOOD
DOWN HERE.
MM-HMM.
THE GAN JINS THINK
SO BADLY OF US,
THEY PROBABLY ASSUMED
WE BROUGHT FOOD IN
AND DECIDED TO BRING
FOOD IN THEMSELVES.
THAT'S WHY WE BROUGHT
FOOD IN.
MMM.
OUR CONFLICT
WITH THE GAN JIN
GOES BACK OVER 100 YEARS.
Zhang: OUR FOREFATHER,
WAI GHIN, WAS LEAVING
THE WESTERN GATE
OF OUR VILLAGE WHEN HE SAW
A FIGURE IN THE DISTANCE.
IT WAS A MAN OF THE GAN JIN
TRIBE--GHIN WAI--
COLLAPSED ON THE GROUND.
NOBLE WAI GHIN STOPPED
TO HELP HIM.
GHIN WAI WAS TRANSPORTING
A SACRED ORB,
A VERY POWERFUL RELIC
USED IN HIS TRIBE'S
REDEMPTION RITUAL.
WAI GHIN TRIED TO TEND
TO THE MAN'S WOUNDS,
BUT GHIN WAI INSISTED THE ORB
WAS MORE IMPORTANT
AND ASKED HIM TO TAKE IT
BACK TO HIS TRIBE.
KIND WAI GHIN PROMISED TO SEND
HELP FOR THE MAN
AS SOON AS HE COULD.
BUT AS WAI GHIN CROSSED
THE BORDER
TO RETURN THE ORB
INTO GAN JIN TERRITORY,
HE WAS ARRESTED.
[SWORDS CLANG]
INSTEAD OF THANKING HIM
FOR HIS KIND AND SELFLESS DEED,
THEY SENTENCED HIM
TO 20 LONG YEARS IN PRISON.
WE ZHANGS WILL NEVER FORGET
THAT INJUSTICE.
THAT'S JUST TERRIBLE.
ARE YOU GONNA
FINISH THAT?
[GRUNTING]
Aang: SURE WOULD BE NICE
TO BE AROUND ONE
OF THOSE CAMPFIRES
TELLING STORIES AND LAUGHING.
IT'S OK, MOMO.
WE'LL BE OUT OF HERE
SOON ENOUGH,
AND THEN WE CAN EAT OUR WEIGHT
IN LITCHI NUTS.
[SQUEAK]
[BUZZING]
[SQUEAKS]
NAH. I'LL WAIT
FOR THE LITCHI NUTS.
Guide: IT'S LONELY,
ISN'T IT, BEING IMPARTIAL?
I WISH I COULD HELP
THESE PEOPLE GET ALONG,
BUT IT JUST
SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE.
ANYHOW, I GUESS
OUR BIGGEST PROBLEM
IS GETTING OUT OF HERE.
I'M NOT SO SURE
THE TWO PROBLEMS
ARE UNRELATED.
ALL CLEAR.
WE'RE ALMOST
TO THE OTHER SIDE.
Aang: KATARA, SOKKO,
WILL THESE PEOPLE
COOPERATE LONG ENOUGH
TO GET OUT
OF THE CANYON?
I DON'T THINK SO,
AANG.
THE ZHANGS REALLY
WRONGED THE GAN JINS.
THEY AMBUSHED GHIN WAI
AND STOLE THE SACRED ORB.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
YEAH, KATARA, WHAT
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WAI GHIN DIDN'T
STEAL THE ORB.
HE WAS RETURNING IT
TO THEIR VILLAGE GATE
AND WAS WRONGFULLY
PUNISHED BY THE GAN JIN.
NOT PUNISHED ENOUGH,
IF YOU ASK ME.
OK, OK. I GET IT.
NOW I NEED YOUR HELP.
LET'S GET EVERYONE
TOGETHER AT THE BASE
OF THE CANYON WALL.
[CROWD CHEERING]
PLEASE, EVERYONE.
AS SOON AS WE GET
OUT OF HERE,
WE CAN EAT AND THEN
GO OUR SEPARATE WAYS.
BUT I NEED YOU ALL
TO PUT YOUR HEADS TOGETHER
AND FIGURE OUT A WAY
UP THIS CLIFF.
MAYBE THE ZHANG
CAN CLIMB THE WALL
WITH THEIR LONG,
DISGUSTING
FINGERNAILS.
Zhang: OH, SORRY.
I FORGOT THAT TO THE GAN JIN,
UNCLIPPED FINGERNAILS
IS A CRIME
PUNISHABLE BY
20 YEARS IN JAIL.
WHY, YOU DIRTY THIEF.
YOU POMPOUS FOOL.
[ALL SHOUTING AT ONCE]
GUYS, FOCUS!
HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO SAY IT?
HARSH WORDS
WON'T SOLVE PROBLEMS.
ACTION WILL!
PERHAPS THE AVATAR
IS RIGHT.
YES. PERHAPS HE IS.
HARSH WORDS WILL NEVER
SOLVE OUR PROBLEMS.
ACTION WILL.
HUH!
AAH!
TO THE DEATH,
AND LET THIS BE THE END
OF THIS RIVALRY.
Aang: YOU KNOW,
I TAKE IT BACK.
HARSH WORDS
AREN'T SO BAD.
HUH?
[GRUNTS]
HYAH!
Aang: IS THAT FOOD?
EVERYONE SMUGGLED
FOOD DOWN HERE?
UNBELIEVABLE!
YOU GUYS PUT
OUR LIVES IN DANGER
BECAUSE YOU COULDN'T GO
WITHOUT A SNACK FOR A DAY?
YOU ARE ALL AWFUL!
SO HUNGRY.
IS THAT EGG CUSTARD
IN THAT TART?
[SCREECHING]
[SHOUTING]
OH, NO. THAT'S
A LOT OF CANYON CRAWLERS.
WE BARELY SURVIVED ONE.
Guide: THEY'RE
COMING BACK FOR ME.
THEY'VE HAD A TASTE,
AND THEY'RE COMING
BACK FOR ME.
SOKKA, WAIT.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT
THE STUPID FEUD.
I JUST WANT US TO GET
OUT OF HERE ALIVE.
ME, TOO. I ONLY
TOOK THEIR SIDE
BECAUSE THEY FED ME.
[SNORTING]
HYAH!
[GASP]
[SHOUTING]
AAH!
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
EVERYBODY, WATCH ME
AND DO WHAT I DO!
NOW FOLLOW ME.
WE'RE RIDING OUT
OF THIS HOLE.
EVERYONE GET OFF!
WE MADE IT!
UH!
HUH!
I NEVER THOUGHT
A GAN JIN
COULD GET HIS HANDS
DIRTY LIKE THAT.
AND I NEVER KNEW
YOU ZHANGS
WERE SO RELIABLE
IN A PINCH.
PERHAPS WE'RE NOT
SO DIFFERENT
AFTER ALL.
[SIGH]
TOO BAD WE CAN'T
REWRITE HISTORY.
YOU THIEVES STOLE
OUR SACRED ORB
FROM GHIN WAI.
YOU TYRANTS UNJUSTLY
IMPRISONED WAI GHIN
FOR 20 LONG YEARS.
UGH. WAIT A SECOND.
GHIN WAI? WAI GHIN?
I KNOW THOSE GUYS.
YES, YES. WE'RE
ALL AWARE OF THE STORY.
NO, I MEAN I REALLY
KNEW THEM.
I MIGHT NOT LOOK IT,
BUT I'M 112 YEARS OLD.
I WAS THERE
100 YEARS AGO
ON THE DAY
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
A LOT OF CONFUSION
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
FIRST OF ALL, GHIN WAI
AND WAI GHIN WEREN'T ENEMIES.
THEY WERE BROTHERS--
TWINS, IN FACT.
AND THEY WERE 8,
AND MOST IMPORTANTLY,
THEY WERE JUST
PLAYING A GAME.
AHH!
- THE SACRED ORB
FROM THE LEGEND--
THAT WAS THE BALL.
AND THE EASTERN
AND WESTERN GATES
WERE THE GOAL POSTS.
GHIN WAI HAD THE BALL
AND WAS RUNNING TOWARD THE GOAL
WHEN HE FELL
AND FUMBLED IT.
WAI GHIN DIDN'T
STEAL THE BALL.
HE PICKED IT UP AND STARTED
RUNNING IT BACK
TOWARD THE OTHER GOAL,
BUT HE STEPPED OUT OF BOUNDS.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
SO THE OFFICIAL PUT HIM
IN THE PENALTY BOX--
NOT FOR 20 LONG YEARS
BUT FOR 2 SHORT MINUTES.
HEE HEE HEE!
THERE WAS NO STEALING
AND NO PUTTING ANYONE
IN PRISON--
JUST A GAME.
YOU'RE SAYING
THE SACRED ORB WAS
ACTUALLY A SACRED BALL?
NOPE, JUST A REGULAR BALL.
WHAT ABOUT OUR TRIBE'S
REDEMPTION RITUAL?
THAT'S WHAT THE GAME
WAS CALLED--REDEMPTION.
AS SOON AS SOMEONE GOT
THE BALL FROM ONE GOAL
TO THE OTHER,
EVERYONE WOULD YELL
"REDEMPTION!"
DON'T GET ME WRONG--
WAI GHIN WAS KIND
OF A SLOB,
AND GHIN WAI WAS
A LITTLE STUFFY.
THAT MUCH IS TRUE.
BUT THEY RESPECTED
EACH OTHER'S DIFFERENCES
ENOUGH TO SHARE
THE SAME PLAYING FIELD.
I SUPPOSE IT'S TIME
WE FORGET THE PAST.
AND LOOK TO THE FUTURE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, BOY.
DID YOU MISS ME?
HA HA HA!
I CANNOT THANK YOU
ENOUGH, AVATAR.
WELL, YOU KNOW.
I TRY.
OH!
LET US TRAVEL
TO THE EARTH
KINGDOM CAPITAL
AS ONE TRIBE.
[CHEERING]
I'M GOING, TOO!
I'M SICK OF THIS PLACE.
THAT'S SOME LUCK
YOU KNEW GHIN WAI
AND WAI GHIN.
YOU COULD CALL IT LUCK,
OR YOU COULD CALL IT
LYING.
WHAT?
I MADE THE WHOLE
THING UP.
YOU DID NOT.
THAT IS SO WRONG.
NOW, WHERE'S
THAT CUSTARD TART?
I'M STARVING!
♪