Katara: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
THIS WHOLE
AVATAR THING.
MAYBE THE MONKS
MADE A MISTAKE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL US YOU WERE
THE AVATAR?
BECAUSE...
I NEVER
WANTED TO BE.
YOU'RE JUST
A BANISHED PRINCE.
YOUR OWN FATHER
DOESN'T EVEN WANT YOU.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
YOU HAVE THE SCAR
TO PROVE IT.
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
WHAT HAPPENED
LAST TIME YOU DUELED
THE MASTER?
- I WILL NEVER FORGET.
Katara:
WE NEED YOU, AANG.
I NEED YOU, TOO.
BE CAREFUL, GUYS!
GUYS?
GYATSO?
Gyatso:
WHY DID YOU DISAPPEAR?
I DIDN'T MEAN TO.
WE NEED YOU, AANG.
[AANG SCREAMS]
Voices:
WE NEED YOU, AANG.
WE NEED YOU.
[MOMO CHITTERS]
HUH!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
DID WE GET CAPTURED
AGAIN?
IT'S NOTHING.
I JUST HAD A BAD DREAM.
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
TELL ME TWICE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, AANG?
I'M OK.
YOU SEEM TO BE HAVING
A LOT OF NIGHTMARES LATELY.
YOU WANT TO TELL ME
ABOUT IT?
I THINK I JUST
NEED SOME REST.
YOU GUYS WANT
TO HEAR ABOUT
MY DREAM?
THAT'S OK.
I DIDN'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT
ANYWAY.
[GRUMBLES]
LOOK AT THOSE
CLEAR SKIES, BUDDY.
SHOULD BE SOME
SMOOTH FLYING.
WELL, WE'D BETTER
SMOOTHLY FLY OURSELVES
TO A MARKET,
BECAUSE WE'RE
OUT OF FOOD.
GUYS, WAIT.
THIS WAS IN MY DREAM.
WE SHOULDN'T GO
TO THE MARKET.
WHAT HAPPENED
IN YOUR DREAM?
FOOD EATS PEOPLE!
ALSO, MOMO COULD TALK.
YOU SAID SOME
VERY UNKIND THINGS.
[CHITTERS]
[SNIFFS]
THERE IS A STORM
COMING.
A BIG ONE.
YOU'RE OUT
OF YOUR MIND, UNCLE.
THE WEATHER IS PERFECT.
THERE'S NOT A CLOUD
IN SIGHT.
A STORM IS APPROACHING
FROM THE NORTH.
I SUGGEST
WE ALTER OUR COURSE
AND HEAD SOUTHWEST.
WE KNOW THE AVATAR
IS TRAVELING NORTHWARD,
SO WE WILL DO THE SAME.
PRINCE ZUKO,
CONSIDER THE SAFETY
OF THE CREW.
THE SAFETY OF THE CREW
DOESN'T MATTER.
FINDING THE AVATAR
IS FAR MORE IMPORTANT
THAN ANY INDIVIDUAL'S
SAFETY.
HE DOESN'T MEAN THAT.
HE'S JUST ALL WORKED UP.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S PERFECT,
I'M TELLING YOU.
[SWISHES]
I DON'T KNOW IF I LIKE
THE SOUND OF THAT SWISHING.
SWISHING MEANS
IT'S RIPE.
IT'S THE RIPE JUICES
SWISHING AROUND, HUH?
I THINK IT'S TRUE,
KATARA.
SWISHING MEANS
IT'S RIPE.
I JUST REALIZED WE'RE
OUT OF MONEY, ANYWAY.
AWW...
OUT OF FOOD
AND OUT OF MONEY.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO DO?
YOU COULD GET A JOB,
SMART GUY.
Woman:
WE SHOULDN'T
GO OUT THERE.
PLEASE!
THE FISH CAN WAIT.
THERE'S GOING TO BE
A TERRIBLE STORM.
AW, YOU'RE CRAZY.
IT'S A NICE DAY.
NO CLOUDS, NO WIND,
NO NOTHING,
SO QUIT YOUR NAGGING,
WOMAN.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
FIND SOME SHELTER.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
SHELTER FROM WHAT?
Woman: MY JOINTS SAY
THERE'S GOING TO BE A STORM,
A BAD ONE.
WELL, IT'S YOUR JOINTS
AGAINST MY BRAIN.
THEN I HOPE YOUR BRAIN
CAN FIND SOMEONE ELSE
TO HAUL THAT FISH,
'CAUSE I AIN'T COMING!
THEN I'LL FIND
A NEW FISH HAULER
AND PAY HIM
DOUBLE WHAT YOU GET.
HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?
I'LL GO.
YOU'RE HIRED.
WHAT? YOU SAID GET A JOB.
AND HE'S PAYING DOUBLE.
DOUBLE? WHO TOLD YOU
THAT NONSENSE?
OH. LOOKS LIKE YOUR
UNCLE WAS RIGHT ABOUT
THE STORM AFTER ALL.
LUCKY GUESS.
LIEUTENANT,
YOU'D BETTER LEARN
SOME RESPECT,
OR I WILL TEACH IT
TO YOU.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT RESPECT?
THE WAY YOU TALK
TO EVERYONE AROUND HERE,
FROM YOUR HARD-WORKING CREW
TO YOUR ESTEEMED UNCLE,
SHOWS YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT RESPECT.
YOU DON'T CARE ABOUT
ANYONE BUT YOURSELF.
THEN AGAIN,
WHAT SHOULD I EXPECT
FROM A SPOILED PRINCE?
EASY NOW.
ENOUGH! WE'RE ALL A BIT TIRED
FROM BEING AT SEA SO LONG.
I'M SURE
AFTER A BOWL OF NOODLES,
EVERYONE WILL FEEL
MUCH BETTER.
I DON'T NEED YOUR HELP
KEEPING ORDER
ON MY SHIP.
SOKKA, MAYBE THIS ISN'T
SUCH A GOOD IDEA.
LOOK AT THE SKY.
I SAID I WAS
GONNA DO THIS JOB.
I CAN'T BACK OUT
JUST BECAUSE OF
SOME BAD WEATHER.
Woman: THE BOY
WITH THE TATTOOS
HAS SOME SENSE.
YOU SHOULD LISTEN
TO HIM.
BOY WITH TATTOOS?
AIRBENDER TATTOOS.
WELL, I'LL BE
A HOG MONKEY'S UNCLE.
YOU'RE THE AVATAR,
AIN'T YOU?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, DON'T BE
SO SMILEY ABOUT IT.
THE AVATAR DISAPPEARED
FOR A HUNDRED YEARS!
YOU TURNED YOUR BACK
ON THE WORLD.
DON'T YELL AT HIM!
AANG WOULD NEVER TURN
HIS BACK ON ANYONE.
OH, HE WOULDN'T,
HUH?
THEN I GUESS
I MUST HAVE
IMAGINED
THE LAST HUNDRED
YEARS OF WAR
AND SUFFERING.
AANG IS THE BRAVEST PERSON
I KNOW.
HE HAS DONE NOTHING
BUT HELP PEOPLE
AND SAVE LIVES
SINCE I MET HIM.
IT'S NOT HIS FAULT
HE DISAPPEARED,
RIGHT, AANG?
AANG, WHAT'S WRONG?
THAT'S RIGHT!
KEEP FLYING!
YOU'RE A HORRIBLE
OLD MAN!
EHH!
APPA, YIP, YIP.
UHH!
HEY! THEY LEFT
WITHOUT SAYING
GOOD-BYE.
YOUR FRIENDS
AIN'T TOO POLITE,
ARE THEY?
I KNOW.
THIS ONE TIME,
I WAS--
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
GET BELOW DECK.
I'M SORRY
FOR RUNNING AWAY.
IT'S OK.
THAT FISHERMAN
WAS WAY OUT OF LINE.
ACTUALLY, HE WASN'T.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
IT HAS TO DO
WITH YOUR DREAM,
DOESN'T IT?
TALK TO ME.
WELL, IT'S KIND
OF A LONG STORY.
[APPA GRUMBLING]
I'M GONNA TRY TO GET
A LITTLE FIRE GOING.
I'LL NEVER FORGET THE DAY
THE MONKS TOLD ME
I WAS THE AVATAR.
I WAS PLAYING WITH
SOME OTHER KIDS JUST
OUTSIDE THE SOUTH WALL.
I WAS TRYING TO TEACH THEM
HOW TO DO THE AIR SCOOTER.
FIRST YOU FORM A BALL.
THEN YOU'VE GOT TO GET ON QUICK.
HA HA HA!
YEAH! HA HA HA!
WHOO-HOO! YEAH!
OK, HERE GOES.
QUICK. GET ON.
WHOA. WHOA...
UHH!
YOU KIND OF HAVE TO BALANCE
ON IT LIKE IT'S A TOP.
MAN, THAT'S HARD.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
THAT TRICK, AANG?
I MADE IT UP.
WOW!
Gyatso: AANG, COME WITH US.
WE NEED TO SPEAK WITH YOU.
Aang:
HOW DO YOU KNOW IT'S ME?
WE HAVE KNOWN
YOU WERE THE AVATAR
FOR SOME TIME.
DO YOU REMEMBER
THESE?
THOSE WERE SOME
OF MY FAVORITE TOYS
WHEN I WAS LITTLE.
YOU CHOSE THEM
FROM AMONG THOUSANDS
OF TOYS, AANG.
THE TOYS YOU PICKED
WERE THE 4
AVATAR RELICS.
THESE ITEMS BELONGED
TO AVATARS PAST.
YOUR OWN PAST LIVES.
I JUST CHOSE THEM
BECAUSE THEY SEEMED FUN.
YOU CHOSE THEM
BECAUSE THEY
WERE FAMILIAR.
NORMALLY,
WE WOULD HAVE TOLD YOU
OF YOUR IDENTITY
WHEN YOU TURNED 16.
BUT THERE ARE
TROUBLING SIGNS.
STORM CLOUDS ARE GATHERING.
I FEAR THAT WAR MAY BE
UPON US, YOUNG AVATAR.
WE NEED YOU, AANG.
I'M SICK
OF TAKING HIS ORDERS,
AND I'M TIRED
OF CHASING HIS AVATAR.
I MEAN, WHO DOES ZUKO
THINK HE IS?
DO YOU REALLY WANT
TO KNOW?
GENERAL IROH,
WE WERE JUST--
IT'S OK.
MAY I JOIN YOU?
OF COURSE, SIR.
TRY TO UNDERSTAND,
MY NEPHEW IS
A COMPLICATED YOUNG MAN.
HE HAS BEEN THROUGH MUCH.
LET ME IN!
PRINCE ZUKO,
WHAT'S WRONG?
I WANT TO GO
INTO THE WAR CHAMBER,
BUT THE GUARD
WON'T LET ME PASS.
YOU'RE NOT
MISSING ANYTHING.
TRUST ME.
THESE MEETINGS
ARE DREADFULLY BORING.
IF I'M GOING TO RULE
THIS NATION ONE DAY,
DON'T YOU THINK
I NEED TO START LEARNING
AS MUCH AS I CAN?
VERY WELL,
BUT YOU MUST PROMISE
NOT TO SPEAK.
THESE OLD FOLKS ARE
A BIT SENSITIVE, YOU KNOW?
THANK YOU, UNCLE.
THE EARTH KINGDOM DEFENSES
ARE CONCENTRATED HERE,
A DANGEROUS BATTALION
OF THEIR STRONGEST EARTHBENDERS
AND FIERCEST WARRIORS.
SO I AM RECOMMENDING
THE 41st DIVISION.
BUT THE 41st IS
ENTIRELY NEW RECRUITS.
HOW DO YOU EXPECT THEM
TO DEFEAT
A POWERFUL EARTH KINGDOM
BATTALION?
I DON'T.
THEY'LL BE USED
AS A DISTRACTION
WHILE WE MOUNT AN ATTACK
FROM THE REAR.
WHAT BETTER TO USE AS BAIT
THAN FRESH MEAT?
YOU CAN'T SACRIFICE
AN ENTIRE DIVISION
LIKE THAT.
THOSE SOLDIERS LOVE
AND DEFEND OUR NATION.
HOW CAN YOU BETRAY THEM?
ZUKO WAS RIGHT, YOU SEE?
BUT IT WAS NOT HIS PLACE
TO SPEAK OUT.
AND THERE WERE
DIRE CONSEQUENCES.
SO YOU WERE UPSET
THAT YOU WERE
THE AVATAR?
WHY WOULDN'T YOU BE
EXCITED ABOUT IT?
WELL, I DIDN'T KNOW
HOW TO FEEL ABOUT IT.
ALL I KNEW WAS
THAT AFTER I FOUND OUT,
EVERYTHING BEGAN CHANGING.
HEY, NOT BAD.
YOU GUYS HAVE
BEEN PRACTICING.
NOT ONLY THAT;
WE MADE UP A GAME
YOU CAN PLAY
WITH THE AIR SCOOTERS.
GREAT!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
NOW THAT YOU'RE
THE AVATAR,
IT'S KIND OF
AN UNFAIR ADVANTAGE
FOR WHICHEVER TEAM
YOU'RE ON.
BUT I'M STILL THE SAME.
NOTHING HAS CHANGED.
SO, WHAT? I CAN'T PLAY?
THAT'S THE ONLY
FAIR WAY.
OH. OK.
SORRY, AANG.
OK, NOW, WHO WANTS
TO HAVE JINJU ON THEIR TEAM?
[LAUGHS]
VERY INTERESTING MOVE,
YOUNG ONE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
HEY! HA HA HA!
HA HA HA!
YOU'RE PLAYING GAMES
WITH HIM?
THE AVATAR
SHOULD BE TRAINING.
AANG HAS ALREADY TRAINED
ENOUGH FOR TODAY.
TIME IS SHORT.
COME WITH ME.
I MUST TEST YOU ON SOME
HIGH-LEVEL TECHNIQUES.
NO. AS LONG AS
I AM HIS GUARDIAN,
I WILL DECIDE
WHEN HE TRAINS
AND WHEN HE GETS
HIS BUTT KICKED AT PAI-SHO.
HMMPH!
AFTER ZUKO'S OUTBURST
IN THE MEETING,
THE FIRE LORD BECAME
VERY ANGRY WITH HIM.
HE SAID THAT PRINCE ZUKO'S
CHALLENGE OF THE GENERAL
WAS AN ACT
OF COMPLETE DISRESPECT.
AND THERE WAS ONLY ONE WAY
TO RESOLVE THIS.
AG NEE KAI.
A FIRE DUEL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ZUKO LOOKED UPON THE OLD GENERAL
HE HAD INSULTED
AND DECLARED
THAT HE WAS NOT AFRAID,
BUT ZUKO MISUNDERSTOOD.
WHEN HE TURNED
TO FACE HIS OPPONENT,
HE WAS SURPRISED TO SEE
IT WAS NOT THE GENERAL.
ZUKO HAD SPOKEN OUT
AGAINST THE GENERAL'S PLAN,
BUT BY DOING SO
IN THE FIRE LORD'S WAR ROOM,
IT WAS THE FIRE LORD
WHOM HE HAD DISRESPECTED.
ZUKO WOULD HAVE TO DUEL
HIS OWN FATHER.
THEN, JUST WHEN I WAS
STARTING TO FEEL BETTER,
SOMETHING WORSE HAPPENED.
AANG NEEDS TO HAVE
FREEDOM AND FUN.
HE NEEDS TO GROW UP
AS A NORMAL BOY.
HMM. YOU CANNOT
KEEP PROTECTING HIM
FROM HIS DESTINY.
GYATSO, I KNOW
YOU MEAN WELL,
BUT YOU ARE LETTING
YOUR AFFECTION FOR THE BOY
CLOUD YOUR JUDGMENT.
ALL I WANT IS WHAT
IS BEST FOR HIM.
BUT WHAT WE NEED
IS WHAT'S BEST FOR THE WORLD.
YOU AND AANG
MUST BE SEPARATED.
THE AVATAR WILL BE SENT AWAY
TO THE EASTERN AIR TEMPLE
TO COMPLETE HIS TRAINING.
THAT'S AWFUL, AANG.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
HOW COULD THEY
DO THAT TO ME?
THEY WANTED TO TAKE AWAY
EVERYTHING I KNEW
AND EVERYONE I LOVED!
WHOA! HOT CINDERS.
I'M SORRY I GOT SO MAD.
YOU HAVE A RIGHT
TO BE ANGRY
AFTER THE MONKS
SENT YOU AWAY LIKE THAT.
WELL, THAT'S NOT EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED.
[LAUGHTER]
I WAS AFRAID AND CONFUSED.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
AANG?
I'M NOT GOING
TO LET THEM TAKE YOU
AWAY FROM ME.
AANG?
[GASPS]
I NEVER SAW GYATSO AGAIN.
[SCREAMS]
[ROARING]
NEXT THING I KNEW,
I WAS WAKING UP IN YOUR ARMS
AFTER YOU FOUND ME
IN THE ICEBERG.
YOU RAN AWAY.
AND THEN THE FIRE NATION
ATTACKED OUR TEMPLE.
MY PEOPLE NEEDED ME,
AND I WASN'T THERE
TO HELP.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT WOULD HAVE--
THE WORLD NEEDED ME,
AND I WASN'T THERE
TO HELP.
AANG--
THE FISHERMAN
WAS RIGHT.
I DID TURN MY BACK
ON THE WORLD.
YOU'RE BEING TOO HARD
ON YOURSELF.
EVEN IF YOU DID RUN AWAY,
I THINK IT WAS MEANT TO BE.
IF YOU HAD STAYED,
YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED
ALONG WITH ALL
THE OTHER AIRBENDERS.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
I KNOW IT'S MEANT
TO BE THIS WAY.
THE WORLD NEEDS YOU NOW.
YOU GIVE PEOPLE HOPE.
[CHITTERS]
Iroh: WHEN PRINCE ZUKO SAW
THAT IT WAS HIS FATHER
WHO HAD COME TO DUEL HIM,
HE BEGGED FOR MERCY.
PLEASE, FATHER,
I ONLY HAD THE FIRE NATION'S
BEST INTERESTS AT HEART.
I'M SORRY I SPOKE
OUT OF TURN.
YOU WILL FIGHT
FOR YOUR HONOR.
I MEANT YOU NO DISRESPECT.
I AM YOUR LOYAL SON.
RISE AND FIGHT,
PRINCE ZUKO.
I WON'T FIGHT YOU.
YOU WILL LEARN RESPECT,
AND SUFFERING
WILL BE YOUR TEACHER.
Iroh, voice-over:
I LOOKED AWAY.
[PRINCE ZUKO SCREAMING]
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
THAT PRINCE ZUKO WAS
IN A TRAINING ACCIDENT.
IT WAS NO ACCIDENT.
AFTER THE DUEL,
THE FIRE LORD SAID
THAT BY REFUSING
TO FIGHT,
ZUKO HAD SHOWN
SHAMEFUL WEAKNESS.
AS PUNISHMENT
HE WAS BANISHED
AND SENT
TO CAPTURE THE AVATAR.
ONLY THEN COULD HE RETURN
WITH HIS HONOR.
SO THAT'S WHY
HE'S SO OBSESSED.
CAPTURING THE AVATAR
IS THE ONLY CHANCE HE HAS
OF THINGS RETURNING
TO NORMAL.
- THINGS WILL NEVER
RETURN TO NORMAL,
BUT THE IMPORTANT THING IS,
THE AVATAR GIVES ZUKO HOPE.
- HELP! OH, PLEASE, HELP!
IT'S OK. YOU'RE SAFE.
BUT MY HUSBAND ISN'T.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHERE'S SOKKA?
THEY HAVEN'T RETURNED.
THEY SHOULD HAVE
BEEN BACK BY NOW.
AND THIS STORM
IS BECOMING A TYPHOON.
THEY'RE CAUGHT
OUT AT SEA!
I'M GOING TO FIND THEM.
I'M GOING WITH YOU.
I'M STAYING HERE.
WE'LL BE BACK SOON.
I PROMISE.
[GRUMBLING]
WHERE WERE WE HIT?
I DON'T KNOW.
LOOK!
Prince Zuko:
THE HELMSMAN!
AAH!
WHERE ARE THEY?
COME ON, APPA!
THE BOAT! THERE!
THE AVATAR!
WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DO, SIR?
LET HIM GO.
WE NEED TO GET THIS SHIP
TO SAFETY.
THEN WE MUST HEAD
DIRECTLY INTO THE EYE
OF THE STORM.
I'M TOO YOUNG TO DIE!
I'M NOT, BUT I STILL
DON'T WANT TO!
[GASPS]
HANG ON TO THE ROPE!
WHOA!
[GASP]
UNCLE, I AM SORRY.
YOUR APOLOGY
IS ACCEPTED.
OH! YOU'RE ALIVE!
YOU OWE THIS BOY
AN APOLOGY.
HE DOESN'T
HAVE TO APOLOGIZE.
WHAT IF,
INSTEAD OF AN APOLOGY,
I GIVE HIM A FREE FISH,
AND WE CALL IT EVEN?
ACTUALLY, I DON'T EAT MEAT.
FISH AIN'T MEAT.
SERIOUSLY, YOU'RE STILL
GONNA PAY ME, RIGHT?
AAH!
KATARA, I THINK YOU
WERE RIGHT BEFORE.
I'M DONE DWELLING
ON THE PAST.
REALLY?
I CAN'T MAKE GUESSES
ABOUT HOW THINGS
WOULD HAVE TURNED OUT IF I
HADN'T RUN AWAY.
I'M HERE NOW, AND I'M GOING
TO MAKE THE MOST OF IT.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE
GONNA HAVE THOSE
NIGHTMARES ANYMORE.
IF YOU WEREN'T
HERE NOW,
WELL, I GUESS
I WOULDN'T BE, EITHER.
THANK YOU FOR SAVING
MY LIFE, AVATAR.
- DO YOU HEAR THAT?
IT STOPPED RAINING.
[GRUMBLES]
Aang: UH! APPA!
♪