Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG,
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
YOU RAN AWAY.
AND THEN THE FIRE
NATION ATTACKED
OUR TEMPLE.
MY PEOPLE NEEDED
ME, AND I WASN'T
THERE TO HELP.
I'M DONE DWELLING
ON THE PAST.
I'M HERE NOW, AND I'M GOING
TO MAKE THE MOST OF IT.
COMMANDER ZHAO, I'VE
BEEN HUNTING THE AVATAR
FOR TWO YEARS AND I--
AND YOU FAILED.
CAPTURING THE AVATAR
IS TOO IMPORTANT TO LEAVE
IN A TEENAGER'S HANDS.
HE'S MINE NOW.
SO THAT'S
WHY HE'S SO OBSESSED.
CAPTURING THE AVATAR
IS THE ONLY CHANCE HE HAS
OF THINGS
RETURNING TO NORMAL.
BUT THE IMPORTANT THING IS
THE AVATAR GIVES ZUKO HOPE.
[BIRD CALLS]
- ABSOLUTELY NOT.
THE YU YAN ARCHERS
STAY HERE.
YOUR REQUEST
IS DENIED,
COMMANDER ZHAO.
COLONEL SHINU,
PLEASE RECONSIDER.
THEIR PRECISION
IS LEGENDARY.
THE YU YAN
CAN PIN A FLY TO A TREE
FROM 100 YARDS AWAY
WITHOUT KILLING IT.
YOU'RE WASTING THEIR
TALENTS USING THEM AS
MERE SECURITY GUARDS.
I CAN DO
WHATEVER I WANT
WITH THEIR TALENTS.
THEY'RE MY ARCHERS,
AND WHAT I SAY GOES.
BUT MY SEARCH
FOR THE AVATAR IS--
IS NOTHING BUT
A VANITY PROJECT.
WE'RE FIGHTING
A REAL WAR HERE,
AND I NEED
EVERY MAN I'VE GOT,
COMMANDER.
BUT--
THAT'S FINAL!
I DON'T WANT
TO HEAR ANOTHER
WORD ABOUT IT.
[BIRD SCREECHES]
NEWS FROM FIRE LORD OZAI?
IT APPEARS I'VE BEEN
PROMOTED TO ADMIRAL.
MY REQUEST IS NOW AN ORDER.
[COUGHING]
THIS SHOULD BRING
YOUR FEVER DOWN.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LOVE
ABOUT APPA THE MOST?
HIS SENSE OF HUMOR.
THAT'S NICE.
I'LL TELL HIM.
HA HA HA!
CLASSIC APPA.
HOW'S SOKKA DOING?
NOT SO GOOD.
BEING OUT IN THAT STORM
REALLY DID
A NUMBER ON HIM.
[SHIVERING]
I COULDN'T FIND
ANY GINGER ROOT
FOR THE TEA,
BUT I FOUND A MAP.
THERE'S AN HERBALIST
INSTITUTE
ON THE TOP
OF THAT MOUNTAIN.
WE COULD PROBABLY
FIND A CURE
FOR SOKKA THERE.
AANG, HE'S IN
NO CONDITION TO TRAVEL.
SOKKA JUST NEEDS
MORE REST.
I'M SURE HE'LL BE
BETTER BY TOMORROW.
[COUGHING]
NOT YOU, TOO.
RELAX. IT WAS JUST
A LITTLE COUGH.
I'M FIN--
[COUGHING]
THAT'S HOW SOKKA
STARTED YESTERDAY.
NOW LOOK AT HIM.
HE THINKS
HE'S AN EARTHBENDER.
TAKE THAT, YOU ROCK.
A FEW MORE HOURS
AND YOU'LL BE
TALKING NONSENSE, TOO.
I'M GOING TO FIND
SOME MEDICINE.
UH, MAYBE IT'S SAFER
IF I GO ON FOOT.
KEEP AN EYE ON THEM, GUYS.
HA HA!
YOU GUYS
ARE KILLING ME.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE
TO PICK UP THE AVATAR'S
TRAIL SINCE THE STORM,
BUT IF WE CONTINUE
HEADING NORTHEAST...
WHAT DO THEY WANT?
PERHAPS A SPORTING
GAME OF PAI SHO.
THE HUNT
FOR THE AVATAR
HAS BEEN GIVEN
PRIME IMPORTANCE.
ALL INFORMATION
REGARDING THE AVATAR
MUST BE REPORTED
DIRECTLY TO
ADMIRAL ZHAO.
ZHAO HAS BEEN
PROMOTED?
WELL,
GOOD FOR HIM.
I'VE GOT NOTHING
TO REPORT TO ZHAO.
NOW GET OFF MY SHIP
AND LET US PASS.
ADMIRAL ZHAO IS NOT
ALLOWING SHIPS
IN OR OUT
OF THIS AREA.
OFF MY SHIP!
EXCELLENT.
I TAKE THE POT.
BUT YOU'RE ALL
IMPROVING.
I'M CERTAIN
YOU WILL WIN IF
WE PLAY AGAIN.
IT SAYS HERE
THAT THE AVATAR CAN
CREATE TORNADOS
AND RUN FASTER
THAN THE WIND.
PRETTY AMAZING.
AW, THAT'S JUST
A BUNCH OF FIRE LORD
PROPAGANDA.
THERE'S NO WAY
THAT'S TRUE.
[BLOWS HORN]
KATARA, PLEASE,
WATER.
LISTEN CAREFULLY, MOMO.
I NEED YOU
TO TAKE THIS TO THE RIVER
AND FILL IT WITH WATER.
[HEARING GIBBERISH]
GOT IT?
- HELLO. I'M SORRY
TO BARGE IN LIKE THIS,
BUT I NEED SOME MEDICINE
FOR MY FRIENDS.
THEY HAVE FEVERS
AND THEY'VE BEEN COUGHING--
SETTLE DOWN, YOUNG MAN.
YOUR FRIENDS
ARE GOING TO BE FINE.
I'VE BEEN UP HERE
FOR OVER 40 YEARS,
YOU KNOW.
USED TO BE OTHERS,
BUT THEY ALL LEFT
YEARS AGO.
NOW IT'S JUST ME
AND MIYUKI.
THAT'S NICE.
WOUNDED EARTH KINGDOM
TROOPS STILL COME BY
NOW AND AGAIN.
BRAVE BOYS,
AND THANKS
TO MY REMEDIES,
THEY ALWAYS
LEAVE IN BETTER SHAPE
THAN WHEN THEY ARRIVED.
THAT'S NICE.
ARE YOU ALMOST DONE?
HOLD ON.
I JUST NEED TO ADD
ONE LAST INGREDIENT.
OH, SANDALWOOD?
OH, YES--
NO, THAT WON'T DO.
BANANA LEAF?
EH, NOPE.
GINGER ROOT?
UH-UH.
OH, WHERE IS THAT
PESKY LITTLE PLANT?
IS EVERYTHING OK?
IT'S BEEN
ALMOST AN HOUR
AND YOU HAVEN'T
GIVEN THE MEN
AN ORDER.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT THEY DO.
DON'T GIVE UP
HOPE YET.
YOU CAN STILL
FIND THE AVATAR
BEFORE ZHAO.
HOW, UNCLE?
WITH ZHAO'S RESOURCES,
IT'S JUST
A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE HE CAPTURES
THE AVATAR.
MY HONOR, MY THRONE,
MY COUNTRY--
I'M ABOUT
TO LOSE THEM ALL.
OH, HERE'S WHAT
I WAS LOOKING FOR.
PLUM BLOSSOM.
FINALLY. THANKS
FOR ALL YOUR HELP.
HANDS OFF.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
TAKING THE CURE
TO MY FRIENDS.
OH! HA HA! THIS
ISN'T A CURE.
IT'S MIYUKI'S
DINNER.
PLUM BLOSSOM
IS HER FAVORITE.
WHAT ABOUT MY FRIENDS?
WELL, ALL THEY NEED
IS SOME FROZEN
WOOD FROGS.
THERE'S PLENTY
OF THEM DOWN
IN THE VALLEY SWAMP.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO
WITH FROZEN FROGS?
WHY, SUCK ON THEM,
OF COURSE.
SUCK ON THEM?
THE FROG SKIN
EXCRETES A SUBSTANCE
THAT'LL CURE
YOUR FRIENDS,
BUT MAKE SURE
YOU GET PLENTY.
ONCE THOSE LITTLE
CRITTERS THAW OUT,
THEY'RE USELESS.
YOU'RE INSANE,
AREN'T YOU?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, DON'T STAND
THERE ALL DAY.
GO!
UH! WHOA!
UH, I THINK
YOU DROPPED THIS.
AAH!
A FROG!
SO THIS IS THE GREAT AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL THE ELEMENTS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU'VE MANAGED TO ELUDE
THE FIRE NATION
FOR 100 YEARS,
BUT YOUR LITTLE GAME
OF HIDE AND SEEK IS OVER.
I'VE NEVER
HIDDEN FROM YOU.
UNTIE ME AND I'LL
FIGHT YOU RIGHT NOW.
UH, NO.
TELL ME, HOW DOES IT
FEEL TO BE THE ONLY
AIRBENDER LEFT?
DO YOU MISS YOUR PEOPLE?
OH, DON'T WORRY.
YOU WON'T BE KILLED
LIKE THEY WERE.
SEE, IF YOU DIE,
YOU'LL JUST BE REBORN
AND THE FIRE NATION
WILL HAVE TO BEGIN
ITS SEARCH FOR THE AVATAR
ALL OVER AGAIN.
SO I'LL KEEP YOU ALIVE,
BUT JUST BARELY.
BLOW ALL THE WIND YOU WANT.
YOUR SITUATION IS FUTILE.
THERE IS NO ESCAPING
THIS FORTRESS
AND NO ONE IS COMING
TO RESCUE YOU.
[COUGHING]
- WATER.
- MOMO SHOULD BE
BACK ANY MINUTE.
NO, MOMO.
WATER.
WA-TER.
AANG, WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS TAKING YOU SO LONG?
ALL CLEAR.
GO ON IN.
WE ARE THE SONS
AND DAUGHTERS OF FIRE,
THE SUPERIOR ELEMENT,
UNTIL TODAY,
ONLY ONE THING STOOD
IN OUR PATH TO VICTORY--
THE AVATAR!
I AM HERE TO TELL YOU
THAT HE IS NOW
MY PRISONER!
[CHEERING]
THIS IS THE YEAR
SOZEN'S COMET RETURNS
TO GRANT US ITS POWER!
[CROWD CHEERING]
THIS IS THE YEAR
THE FIRE NATION
BREAKS THROUGH
THE WALLS OF BA SING SE,
AND BURNS THE CITY
TO THE GROUND.
[CHEERING]
WHAT? NO!
DON'T LEAVE, FROGS.
MY FRIENDS ARE SICK
AND THEY NEED YOU.
PLEASE GO BACK
TO BEING FROZEN.
[RIBBIT RIBBIT]
[PUNCHES BEING THROWN]
AAH!
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
ARE YOU HERE
TO RESCUE ME?
I'LL TAKE THAT
AS A YES.
MY FROGS!
COME BACK!
AND STOP
THAWING OUT!
WAIT!
MY FRIENDS
NEED TO SUCK ON
THOSE FROGS!
HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO
TELL YOU, MOMO?
WE NEED WATER.
WA-TER.
OH, FORGET IT.
AANG, PLEASE HURRY.
WHO IS THIS AANG KID
YOU KEEP TALKING ABOUT,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
I WANT A FULL
TRANSCRIPTION
OF MY SPEECH
SENT TO
THE FIRE LORD,
ALONG WITH
GLOWING TESTIMONIALS
FROM ALL OF
THE RANKING OFFICERS
PRESENT, AND--
[MEN GRUNTING]
[RIBBIT]
SIR, SHALL I HOLD OFF
SENDING THAT SPEECH
TO THE FIRE LORD?
[NOISY CHIMES RINGING]
THERE. ON THE WALL!
AAH!
THE AVATAR HAS ESCAPED!
CLOSE ALL THE GATES
IMMEDIATELY.
STAY CLOSE TO ME.
AAH!
[YELLS]
TAKE THIS.
JUMP ON MY BACK!
GIVE ME THE NEXT ONE!
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
THE AVATAR MUST BE
CAPTURED ALIVE.
OPEN THE GATE.
ADMIRAL,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LET THEM OUT.
NOW!
HOW COULD YOU
LET THEM GO?
A SITUATION LIKE THIS
REQUIRES...PRECISION.
DO YOU HAVE
A CLEAR SHOT?
KNOCK OUT THE THIEF.
I'LL DELIVER HIM
TO THE FIRE LORD
ALONG WITH THE AVATAR.
QUICK!
RECOVER THE AVATAR!
[RIBBIT]
- YOU KNOW WHAT
THE WORST PART
ABOUT BEING BORN
OVER 100 YEARS AGO IS?
I MISS ALL THE FRIENDS
I USED TO HANG OUT WITH.
BEFORE THE WAR STARTED,
I USED TO ALWAYS
VISIT MY FRIEND,
KUZON.
THE TWO OF US,
WE'D GET IN AND OUT
OF SO MUCH
TROUBLE TOGETHER.
HE WAS ONE
OF THE BEST FRIENDS
I EVER HAD...
AND HE WAS FROM
THE FIRE NATION,
JUST LIKE YOU.
IF WE KNEW EACH
OTHER BACK THEN,
DO YOU THINK
WE COULD HAVE
BEEN FRIENDS, TOO?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN,
PRINCE ZUKO?
YOU MISSED MUSIC NIGHT.
LIEUTENANT JEE SANG
A STIRRING LOVE SONG.
- I'M GOING TO BED.
NO DISTURBANCES.
[PLAYING INSTRUMENT]
SUCK ON THESE.
IT'LL MAKE YOU
FEEL BETTER.
AANG,
HOW WAS YOUR TRIP?
DID YOU MAKE
ANY NEW FRIENDS?
NO.
I DON'T THINK I DID.
MM!
THIS IS TASTY.
MM, MM!
[RIBBIT]
PTOOEY!
AAH!