Katara: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE,
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
MMM...
[GASP]
WHY ARE YOU SMILING
AT ME LIKE THAT?
OH. I WAS SMILING?
UGH!
I KNOW, I KNOW.
THAT WAS STUPID
AND DANGEROUS.
[SIGH]
AANG IS THE AVATAR.
HE'S THE WORLD'S
ONLY CHANCE.
NOW YOUR DESTINIES
ARE INTERTWINED WITH HIS.
- LOOK!
HE IS TAUNTING US.
YOU ARE SO
GOING TO BE DINNER.
HEY, WHERE'S
THE FISHING LINE?
OH, I DIDN'T THINK
YOU WOULD NEED IT,
SOKKA.
AH, IT'S ALL TANGLED.
- NOT TANGLED, WOVEN.
I MADE YOU
A NECKLACE, KATARA.
I THOUGHT
SINCE YOU LOST
YOUR OTHER ONE...
THANKS, AANG.
I LOVE IT.
GREAT, AANG.
MAYBE INSTEAD
OF SAVING THE WORLD,
YOU CAN GO INTO
THE JEWELRY-MAKING BUSINESS.
I DON'T SEE WHY
I CAN'T DO BOTH.
HUH!
STOP TAUNTING ME!
UHH!
Katara:
SO, HOW DO I LOOK?
YOU MEAN, ALL OF YOU
OR JUST YOUR NECK--
I MEAN,
BECAUSE THEY BOTH
LOOK GREAT.
SMOOCHIE SMOOCHIE.
SOMEONE'S IN LOVE.
I, WELL--
STOP TEASING HIM,
SOKKA.
AANG'S JUST
A GOOD FRIEND,
A SWEET LITTLE GUY,
JUST LIKE MOMO.
THANKS.
[GROWLING]
SOMEONE'S BEING ATTACKED
BY A PLATYPUS BEAR!
WELL, HELLO THERE.
NICE DAY, ISN'T IT?
MAKE NOISE!
HE'LL RUN OFF!
NO, PLAY DEAD!
HE'LL LOSE INTEREST!
WHOA, CLOSE ONE.
HA HA HA.
RUN DOWNHILL,
THEN CLIMB A TREE!
NO, PUNCH HIM
IN THE BILL!
AND THEN RUN
IN ZIG-ZAGS.
NO NEED.
IT'S GOING TO
BE FINE.
WHOA, THERE.
MMM, LUNCH.
[SNIFFS]
LUCKY FOR YOU
WE CAME ALONG.
THANKS, BUT EVERYTHING
WAS ALREADY UNDER CONTROL.
NOT TO WORRY.
AUNT WU PREDICTED
I'D HAVE A SAFE JOURNEY.
AUNT WHO?
NO, AUNT WU.
SHE'S THE FORTUNE-TELLER
FROM MY VILLAGE.
AWFUL NICE
KNOWING YOUR FUTURE.
WOW, IT MUST BE.
THAT EXPLAINS WHY
YOU WERE SO CALM.
BUT THE FORTUNE-TELLER
WAS WRONG.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE
A SAFE JOURNEY.
YOU WERE ALMOST KILLED.
BUT I WASN'T.
ALL RIGHT,
HAVE A GOOD ONE.
OH, AND AUNT WU SAID
IF I MET ANY TRAVELERS,
TO GIVE THEM THIS.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
GO SEE AUNT WU
AND LEARN OUR FORTUNES.
IT COULD BE FUN.
OH, COME ON.
FORTUNE-TELLING
IS NONSENSE.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
AN UMBRELLA.
[THUNDER]
THAT PROVES IT.
NO, IT DOESN'T.
YOU CAN'T REALLY
TELL THE FUTURE.
I GUESS YOU'RE NOT
REALLY GETTING WET,
THEN.
WHOA--AAH!
OF COURSE
SHE PREDICTED
IT WAS GONNA
RAIN.
THE SKY HAS BEEN
GREY ALL DAY.
JUST ADMIT
YOU MIGHT BE WRONG,
AND YOU CAN COME
UNDER THE UMBRELLA.
LOOK, I'M GONNA PREDICT
THE FUTURE NOW.
IT'S GOING TO
KEEP DRIZZLING.
SEE?
NOT EVERYONE
HAS THE GIFT,
SOKKA.
AAH!
[QUACKING]
AUNT WU IS EXPECTING YOU.
REALLY?
PFFT.
MY NAME IS MENG,
AND I'M AUNT WU'S
ASSISTANT.
WELL, HELLO THERE.
HELLO.
CAN I GET YOU SOME TEA
OR SOME OF AUNT WU'S
SPECIAL BEAN CURD PUFFS?
I'LL TRY
A CURD PUFF.
JUST A SECOND.
SO, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
AANG.
THAT RHYMES WITH MENG,
AND YOU'VE GOT
SOME PRETTY BIG EARS,
DON'T YOU?
I GUESS.
DON'T BE MODEST.
THEY'RE HUGE.
- WELL, AANG,
IT'S VERY NICE
TO MEET YOU--
VERY NICE.
- LIKEWISE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE'RE HERE
IN THE HOUSE
OF NONSENSE.
TRY TO KEEP
AN OPEN MIND, SOKKA.
THERE ARE THINGS
IN THIS WORLD
THAT JUST CAN'T
BE EXPLAINED.
WOULDN'T IT BE NICE
TO HAVE SOME INSIGHT
INTO YOUR FUTURE?
IT WOULD BE NICE
TO HAVE SOME
BEAN CURD PUFFS.
- OH, MENG!
AUNT WU SAYS
I'M GOING TO MEET
MY TRUE LOVE!
HE'S GOING TO GIVE ME
A RARE PANDA LILY.
THAT'S SO ROMANTIC.
I WONDER IF MY TRUE LOVE
WILL GIVE ME A RARE FLOWER.
GOOD LUCK WITH THAT.
[CHUCKLE]
IS THAT THE BIG-EARED GUY
WHO AUNT WU PREDICTED
YOU'D MARRY?
AAH!
ENJOY YOUR SNACK.
- WELCOME,
YOUNG TRAVELERS.
NOW, WHO'S NEXT?
DON'T BE SHY.
I GUESS THAT'S ME.
NOT BAD,
NOT BAD.
MMM! MMM!
HMM?
I'M GOOD ON PUFFS.
HMM.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT
BACK THERE?
BORING STUFF,
I'M SURE.
LOVE, WHO SHE'S
GONNA MARRY,
HOW MANY BABIES
SHE'S GONNA
HAVE.
YEAH, DUMB STUFF
LIKE THAT.
WELL, I GOTTA
FIND A BATHROOM.
Aunt Wu: YOUR PALMS
ARE SO SMOOTH.
DO YOU USE MOISTURIZER?
Katara: ACTUALLY,
I HAVE THIS SPECIAL
SEAWEED LOTION.
I COULD GET YOU SOME
IF YOU WANT.
SO, DO YOU SEE
ANYTHING INTERESTING
IN MY LOVE LINE?
I SEE A GREAT
ROMANCE FOR YOU--
THE MAN YOU'RE
GOING TO MARRY.
TELL ME MORE!
I CAN SEE THAT
HE'S A VERY POWERFUL BENDER.
LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE
HAD A PRETTY GOOD
BATHROOM BREAK.
YEAH, WHEN I WAS IN THERE--
I DON'T EVEN
WANT TO KNOW.
WHO'S NEXT?
OK, LET'S GET THIS
OVER WITH.
YOUR FUTURE IS FULL
OF STRUGGLE AND ANGUISH,
MOST OF IT SELF-INFLICTED.
BUT YOU
DIDN'T READ MY PALMS
OR ANYTHING.
I DON'T NEED TO.
IT'S WRITTEN ALL OVER
YOUR FACE.
YOU THERE,
COME WITH ME.
THIS IS THE MOST
RELIABLE METHOD OF
TELLING YOUR FORTUNE.
THE BONES NEVER LIE.
GO ON. PICK ONE.
NOW THROW IT
ON THE FIRE.
THE HEAT MAKES
CRACKS IN THE BONES,
AND I READ THE BONE CRACKS
TO TELL YOUR DESTINY.
Aang: WOW,
THAT'S A BIG CRACK.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS
BEFORE.
[GASPS]
OH, MY!
YOUR DESTINY--
THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
YOU WILL BE INVOLVED
IN A GREAT BATTLE--
AN AWESOME CONFLICT
BETWEEN THE FORCES
OF GOOD AND EVIL.
A BATTLE WHOSE OUTCOME
WILL DETERMINE THE FATE
OF THE WHOLE WORLD.
YEAH, YEAH.
I KNEW THAT ALREADY,
BUT DID IT
SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
A GIRL?
YOU WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT LOVE?
YES!
I'M SORRY,
BUT I DIDN'T SEE ANYTHING.
OH, LOOK!
I MUST HAVE
MISSED SOMETHING.
RIGHT HERE.
IT SAYS, "TRUST YOUR HEART,
AND YOU WILL BE WITH
THE ONE YOU LOVE."
REALLY?
THANK YOU, AUNT WU!
Sokka:
WELL, NOW YOU GOT TO
SEE FOR YOURSELVES
THAT FORTUNE-TELLING
IS JUST A BIG,
STUPID HOAX.
YOU'RE JUST
SAYING THAT
BECAUSE YOU'RE GONNA
MAKE YOURSELF UNHAPPY
YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
THAT WOMAN IS CRAZY!
MY LIFE WILL BE
CALM AND HAPPY
AND JOYFUL!
OW!
THAT DOESN'T PROVE
ANYTHING.
WELL, I LIKED
MY PREDICTIONS.
CERTAIN THINGS
ARE GONNA TURN
OUT VERY WELL.
THEY SURE ARE.
WHY?
WHAT DID SHE
TELL YOU?
SOME STUFF.
YOU'LL FIND OUT.
WHAT'S WITH THE SKY?
WE'RE WAITING
FOR AUNT WU TO COME
AND READ THE CLOUDS
TO PREDICT THE FATE
OF THE WHOLE
VILLAGE.
THAT CLOUD KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE A FLUFFY BUNNY.
YOU BETTER HOPE
THAT'S NOT A BUNNY.
THE FLUFFY BUNNY
CLOUD FORECASTS DOOM
AND DESTRUCTION.
DO YOU EVEN
HEAR YOURSELF?
THE CLOUD READING
WILL TELL US
IF MOUNT MAKAPU
WILL REMAIN DORMANT
FOR ANOTHER YEAR
OR IF IT WILL ERUPT.
WE USED TO HAVE
A TRADITION
ONCE A YEAR
OF GOING UP
THE MOUNTAIN
TO CHECK THE VOLCANO
OURSELVES,
BUT EVER SINCE
AUNT WU
MOVED TO THE VILLAGE
20 YEARS AGO,
WE HAVE A TRADITION
OF NOT DOING THAT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU WOULD
TRUST YOUR LIVES
TO THAT CRAZY
OLD WOMAN'S
SUPERSTITION!
SHH! SHE'S COMING.
[CHEERING]
HEY, AANG,
DON'T YOU THINK
THAT CLOUD LOOKS
LIKE A FLOWER, HUH?
SURE, I GUESS.
HEY, KATARA,
DON'T YOU THINK THAT CLOUD
LOOKS LIKE A FLOWER?
SHH!
BENDING ARROW CLOUD--
GOOD CROPS THIS YEAR.
NICE, BIG HARVEST.
DARN GOOD NEWS!
WAVY MOON-SHAPE CLOUD--
LET'S SEE.
GONNA BE A GREAT YEAR
FOR TWINS.
-YES!
AND A CUMULOUS CLOUD
WITH A TWISTY NUB COMING
OFF THE END OF IT--
THE VILLAGE
WILL NOT BE DESTROYED BY
THE VOLCANO THIS YEAR!
[CHEERING]
- SINCE I GOT YOU
HERE,
THERE'S SOMETHING
I WANT TO TELL YOU.
I LIKE YOU, BUT MORE
THAN NORMAL.
NEVER MIND.
- HI, AUNT WU.
SORRY TO BOTHER YOU.
ANYTIME.
ABOUT THIS MAN
I'M SUPPOSED
TO MARRY--
IS HE GONNA BE
HANDSOME?
OH, I HOPE
HE'S TALL.
AH. YOU WANT
ANOTHER READING.
YES, PLEASE.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE
ALL THESE SAPS.
SOMEONE REALLY NEEDS
TO SCREAM SOME SENSE AT THEM.
THEY SEEM HAPPY,
SOKKA.
NOT FOR LONG.
I'M GONNA PROVE
AUNT WU'S PREDICTIONS
ARE NONSENSE.
HEY, YOU,
I BET AUNT WU
TOLD YOU TO WEAR
THOSE RED SHOES,
DIDN'T SHE?
YEAH, SHE SAID
I'D BE WEARING RED SHOES
WHEN I MET
MY TRUE LOVE.
UH-HUH.
AND HOW MANY TIMES
HAVE YOU WORN
THOSE SHOES
SINCE YOU GOT
THAT FORTUNE?
EVERY DAY.
THEN OF COURSE
IT'S GONNA
COME TRUE!
REALLY?
YOU THINK SO?
I'M SO EXCITED!
UHH!
[SQUAWKING]
AAH! UHH!
AND THEN YOU'LL HAVE
YOUR THIRD GREAT GRANDCHILD
BEFORE QUIETLY
PASSING AWAY
IN YOUR SLEEP.
IS THAT ENOUGH
INFORMATION FOR YOU?
WOW.
THANKS, AUNT WU.
OH, WAIT.
ONE MORE THING.
HOW WARMLY SHOULD I
DRESS TOMORROW?
YOU WANT ME TO DO
A READING FOR THAT?
I DON'T CARE
WHAT AUNT WU TOLD YOU!
YOU HAVE TO TAKE A BATH
SOMETIME!
[CHUCKLING]
SO, SOKKA,
YOU KNOW SOME STUFF
ABOUT LADIES, RIGHT?
SOME STUFF?
YOU'VE COME TO
THE RIGHT PLACE.
WHAT CAN I DO
YOU FOR?
WELL, THERE'S THIS GIRL...
[GIGGLING]
I THINK I KNOW
WHO YOU MEAN.
YOU DO?
AND YOU'RE OK WITH IT?
OF COURSE I AM.
AND TO TELL YOU
THE TRUTH,
I'VE BEEN PICKING UP
A SUBTLE VIBE THAT
SHE LIKES YOU, TOO.
SHE DOES?
OH, YEAH.
SHE'S CRAZY
ABOUT YOU.
ALL YOU
HAVE TO DO NOW
IS NOT MESS IT UP.
WELL, HOW DO I DO THAT?
THE NUMBER ONE
MISTAKE NICE GUYS
LIKE YOU MAKE--
BEING TOO NICE.
YOU CAN BE TOO NICE?
YEP. IF YOU WANT TO
KEEP HER INTERESTED,
YOU HAVE TO ACT
ALOOF,
LIKE YOU DON'T
REALLY CARE ONE WAY
OR THE OTHER.
WELL, OK.
HEY, AANG.
I WAS WONDERING--
SEE YOU LATER.
HMM.
WOW.
THAT KID IS GOOD.
AND YOU'LL BE FINE
AS LONG AS YOU'VE
GOT A SCARF.
BYE-BYE, NOW.
OK, OK.
BUT ONE MORE THING.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT IS IT?
SHOULD I EAT
A MANGO OR A PAPAYA
FOR BREAKFAST TOMORROW?
PAPAYA.
OH, I HATE PAPAYA.
OH. HEY, KATARA.
I DIDN'T
SEE YOU THERE.
HEY, AANG.
THAT'S OK.
I'M BUSY WITH
MY OWN STUFF.
[QUACK]
UGH. PAPAYA, PLEASE.
SO, PAPAYA.
UH-HUH.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME?
YOU KNOW ME.
I DON'T REALLY CARE
WHAT I EAT.
OK, THEN.
SEE YOU LATER.
UGH!
MAYBE ALOOF
ISN'T MY STYLE.
OH, A PANDA LILY.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
EXCUSE ME.
WHERE CAN A GUY FIND
ONE OF THOSE THINGS?
Sokka: I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE DRAGGING ME
ALL THE WAY UP HERE
FOR A STUPID FLOWER.
NOT JUST ANY FLOWER--
A PANDA LILY.
I'VE SEEN IT IN ACTION,
AND, BOY, DOES IT WORK.
FLOWERS ARE FINE
ONCE YOU'RE MARRIED,
BUT AT THIS EARLY STAGE,
IT'S CRITICAL
THAT YOU MAINTAIN
MAXIMUM ALOOFNESS.
BUT MY HEART
IS TELLING ME
TO GET THIS FLOWER,
AND AUNT WU SAID
IF I TRUSTED MY HEART,
I WOULD BE WITH
THE ONE I LOVE.
WHAT?
DON'T TELL ME
YOU BELIEVE IN
THAT STUFF, TOO.
WELL, AUNT WU HASN'T
BEEN WRONG YET.
WHY SHOULD SHE BE WRONG
ABOUT LOVE?
THERE, ON THE RIM!
[GASP]
OH, NO.
AUNT WU WAS WRONG.
THOSE PEOPLE
ALL THINK THEY'RE SAFE.
WE'VE GOT TO WARN THEM.
THERE'S NO TIME
TO WALK.
GRAB ON.
AAH!
HI, KATARA.
CAN YOU BELIEVE SHE
WON'T LET ME IN?
AND AFTER ALL
THE BUSINESS
I'VE GIVEN HER?
BUT SHE DOESN'T
EVEN CHARGE.
I KNOW, BUT STILL.
WELL, WE HAVE
OTHER THINGS
TO WORRY ABOUT.
AUNT WU WAS WRONG
ABOUT THE VOLCANO.
SOKKA, YOU TRIED
TO CONVINCE ME SHE
WAS WRONG BEFORE.
IT'S GONNA TAKE
AN AWFUL LOT
TO CHANGE MY--
[RUMBLING]
OH, NO.
Sokka: EVERYONE,
THAT VOLCANO IS GONNA
BLOW ANY SECOND!
AUNT WU WAS WRONG!
YEAH, YEAH.
WE KNOW YOU DON'T
BELIEVE IN AUNT WU,
MR. SCIENCE
AND REASON LOVER.
IF YOU WON'T LISTEN TO HIM,
MAYBE YOU'LL LISTEN TO ME.
I WANT TO BELIEVE AUNT WU
AND HER PREDICTIONS
AS MUCH AS YOU DO,
BUT MY BROTHER AND AANG
SAW THE LAVA
WITH THEIR OWN EYES.
WELL, I HEARD
AUNT WU'S PREDICTION
WITH MY OWN EARS.
PLEASE LISTEN TO US!
YOU ARE ALL IN DANGER,
AND WE HAVE TO
GET OUT OF HERE!
YOU CAN'T RELY
ON AUNT WU'S PREDICTIONS!
YOU HAVE TO TAKE FATE
INTO YOUR OWN HANDS!
LOOK!
CAN YOUR FORTUNE-TELLING
EXPLAIN THAT?
HEH. CAN YOUR SCIENCE
EXPLAIN WHY IT RAINS?
YES!
YES, IT CAN!
THEY JUST WON'T
LISTEN TO REASON.
BUT THEY WILL LISTEN
TO AUNT WU.
I KNOW.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
WELL, IT'S ABOUT TO
BECOME THE SOLUTION.
WE'RE TAKING FATE
IN OUR OWN HANDS.
FIRST, I NEED
TO BORROW AUNT WU'S
CLOUD-READING BOOK.
[CHATTERS]
SHH.
WE DON'T WANT ANYONE
TO HEAR US.
OH! OH, I DIDN'T
SEE YOU THERE.
YOU DON'T LIKE ME,
DO YOU?
- OF COURSE
I LIKE YOU.
- BUT NOT THE WAY
- OH. I GUESS NOT.
IT'S OK.
IT'S JUST REALLY HARD
WHEN YOU LIKE SOMEONE,
BUT THEY DON'T THINK
OF YOU THAT WAY.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN.
- SHE'S BEAUTIFUL,
BY THE WAY.
HUH?
- THAT WATER TRIBE GIRL.
I CAN SEE WHY
YOU LIKE HER SO MUCH.
SHE'S SWEET,
SHE'S A BENDER,
AND HER HAIR SEEMS
SO MANAGEABLE.
- DON'T WORRY.
YOU'RE GONNA
MEET A GREAT GUY
WHO'S GONNA
COMPLETELY
FALL FOR YOU.
I KNOW IT.
- THANKS.
WAIT.
DON'T YOU WANT THIS?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
I'VE KIND OF BEEN
STALKING YOU. HEH.
OH, THANKS...
I GUESS.
[GRUMBLING]
Aang: CLOUDS ARE MADE
OF WATER AND AIR,
SO BETWEEN THE TWO OF US,
WE OUGHT TO BE ABLE
TO BEND THEM INTO
ANY SHAPE WE WANT.
I FOUND IT--
THE SYMBOL
FOR VOLCANIC DOOM.
[GRUMBLING]
Sokka:
AUNT WU, LOOK!
SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING
IN THE CLOUDS!
THAT'S VERY STRANGE.
IT SHOULDN'T--
OH, MY!
Aang: WE COULD STILL
SAVE THE VILLAGE
IF WE ACT FAST.
SOKKA HAS A PLAN.
LAVA IS GONNA FLOW
DOWNHILL TO THIS SPOT.
IF WE CAN DIG
A DEEP ENOUGH TRENCH,
WE CAN CHANNEL ALL THE LAVA
AWAY FROM THE VILLAGE
TO THE RIVER.
IF ANY OF YOU
ARE EARTH BENDERS,
COME WITH ME.
I'M AN EARTH BENDER!
I'M NOT!
EVERYBODY ELSE,
GRAB A SHOVEL.
[CROWD GASPS]
COME ON!
WE'VE GOT TO HURRY.
[SHOUTING]
[GASP]
DIG FASTER! DIG FASTER!
EVERYONE NEEDS
TO EVACUATE!
WE'LL COME FOR YOU
WHEN IT'S SAFE!
[CHATTERS]
Katara:
IT'S TOO MUCH.
IT'S GONNA
OVERFLOW!
AAH!
UHH!
MAN...
SOMETIMES I FORGET
WHAT A POWERFUL BENDER
THAT KID IS.
WAIT, WHAT DID
YOU JUST SAY?
NOTHING. JUST THAT AANG
IS ONE POWERFUL BENDER.
I SUPPOSE HE IS.
Aang: BY THE WAY,
WE KIND OF BORROWED
YOUR BOOK.
- SO YOU MESSED WITH
THE CLOUDS, DID YOU?
HA HA HA!
VERY CLEVER.
- NO OFFENSE, BUT I HOPE THIS
HAS TAUGHT EVERYONE
A LESSON
ABOUT NOT RELYING
TOO MUCH ON
FORTUNE-TELLING.
BUT AUNT WU PREDICTED
THE VILLAGE WOULDN'T
BE DESTROYED,
AND IT WASN'T.
SHE WAS RIGHT,
AFTER ALL.
I HATE YOU.
IT'S OK, SOKKA.
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT.
- CAN I ASK YOU
SOMETHING?
OF COURSE, HONEY.
YOU DIDN'T REALLY
SEE LOVE IN MY
FORTUNE, DID YOU?
YOU JUST TOLD ME
WHAT I WANTED
TO HEAR.
I'LL TELL YOU
A LITTLE SECRET,
YOUNG AIR BENDER.
JUST AS YOU
RESHAPED THOSE CLOUDS,
YOU HAVE THE POWER
TO SHAPE YOUR OWN DESTINY.
Katara:
GOOD-BYE, EVERYONE!
IT WAS SO NICE
TO MEET YOU!
TAKE CARE, MENG.
TAKE CARE!
FLOOZY.