Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS, COULD
STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG,
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
100 YEARS HAVE PASSED,
AND THE FIRE NATION
IS NEARING VICTORY IN THE WAR.
TWO YEARS AGO, MY FATHER
AND THE MEN OF MY TRIBE
JOURNEYED TO THE EARTH KINGDOM
TO HELP FIGHT AGAINST
THE FIRE NATION,
LEAVING ME AND MY BROTHER
TO LOOK AFTER OUR TRIBE.
TRY TO UNDERSTAND,
I NEED TO CAPTURE HIM
TO RESTORE SOMETHING
I'VE LOST--
MY HONOR.
PERHAPS IN EXCHANGE, I CAN
RESTORE SOMETHING YOU'VE LOST.
MY MOTHER'S NECKLACE.
HEY, LOOK!
A SWORD MADE OUT OF
A WHALE'S TOOTH!
LET ME SEE THAT.
THIS IS
A WATER TRIBE
WEAPON.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
ANYTHING ELSE.
DID SOMEONE
LOSE SOMETHING?
NO, WE FOUND
SOMETHING.
IT'S BURNED.
THERE WAS A BATTLE.
WATER TRIBE WARRIORS
AMBUSHED A GROUP OF
FIREBENDERS.
THE FIREBENDERS
FOUGHT BACK,
BUT THE WARRIORS
DROVE THEM DOWN
THIS HILL.
SO THEN
WHAT HAPPENED?
I DON'T KNOW.
THE TRAIL
ENDS HERE.
WAIT! LOOK!
IT'S ONE OF
OUR BOATS!
Katara:
IS THIS DAD'S BOAT?
NO, BUT IT'S
FROM HIS FLEET.
DAD WAS HERE.
AHH!
SEE, PRINCE ZUKO?
A MOMENT OF QUIET
IS GOOD FOR
YOUR MENTAL WELL-BEING.
UNH!
[GRUNTS]
WATCH OUT!
[GROWLING]
GET BACK!
WE'RE AFTER A STOWAWAY.
THERE ARE NO STOWAWAYS
ON MY SHIP.
[MAN BREATHING HEAVILY]
HE'S PARALYZED.
ONLY TEMPORARILY.
THE TOXINS WILL WEAR OFF
IN ABOUT AN HOUR,
BUT BY THEN,
HE'LL BE IN JAIL
AND I'LL HAVE
MY MONEY.
BUT HOW DID YOU
FIND HIM ON MY SHIP?
MY XIERXU CAN SMELL A RAT
A CONTINENT AWAY.
WELL, I'M IMPRESSED.
VERY IMPRESSED.
SOKKA.
I'M COMING WITH YOU.
YOU'RE NOT OLD ENOUGH
TO GO TO WAR, SOKKA.
YOU KNOW THAT.
I'M STRONG. I'M BRAVE.
I CAN FIGHT!
PLEASE, DAD?
BEING A MAN IS KNOWING
WHERE YOU'RE NEEDED
THE MOST,
AND FOR YOU RIGHT NOW,
THAT'S HERE PROTECTING
YOUR SISTER.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
SOMEDAY YOU WILL.
I'M GONNA MISS YOU
SO MUCH.
[SOBBING]
WHO'S THERE?
SOKKA?
BATO?
WHO THE WHAT NOW?
BATO!
SAKKO! KATARA!
IT IS SO GOOD
TO SEE YOU TWO.
OH. YOU'VE GROWN
SO MUCH.
HI. I'M AANG.
WHERE'S
DAD?
IS HE HERE?
NO. HE AND THE OTHER WARRIORS
SHOULD BE IN THE EASTERN
EARTH KINGDOM BY NOW.
[WIND BLOWING]
[SHUDDER]
THIS IS NO PLACE
FOR A REUNION.
LET'S GET INSIDE.
AFTER I WAS WOUNDED,
YOUR FATHER CARRIED ME
TO THIS ABBEY.
THE SISTERS HAVE CARED FOR ME
EVER SINCE.
SUPERIOR, THESE ARE
KOTA'S CHILDREN.
THEY'VE BEEN TRAVELING
WITH THE AVATAR.
I FOUND THEM BY MY BOAT.
YOUNG AVATAR,
IT GIVES ME GREAT JOY
TO BE
IN YOUR PRESENCE.
WELCOME TO OUR ABBEY.
THANK YOU.
IT'S TRULY AN HONOR
TO BE HERE.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING--
WHAT SMELLS SO GOOD,
BATO?
[SNIFFS]
THE SISTERS CRAFT
OINTMENTS AND PERFUMES.
PERFUME?
MAYBE WE COULD
DUMP SOME ON APPA,
BECAUSE HE STINKS
SO MUCH.
AM I RIGHT?
[PERSON COUGHS]
YOU HAVE
YOUR FATHER'S WIT.
BATO,
IT LOOKS LIKE HOME!
EVERYTHING'S HERE,
EVEN THE PELTS.
YEAH. NOTHING'S COZIER
THAN DEAD ANIMAL SKINS.
ACK!
NO WAY!
STEWED SEA PRUNES?
HELP YOURSELF.
DAD COULD EAT
A WHOLE BARREL
OF THESE THINGS.
[SNIFFS]
UGH!
BATO, IS IT TRUE
YOU AND DAD LASSOED
AN ARCTIC HIPPO?
IT WAS
YOUR FATHER'S IDEA.
HE JUST DRAGGED ME ALONG.
WELL, THE HIPPO
DID THE DRAGGING.
HEY, I RIDE
ANIMALS, TOO!
ONE TIME, THERE WAS
THIS GIANT EEL,
AND I--
SO, WHO WAS IT
THAT CAME UP WITH THE GREAT
BLUBBER FIASCO?
YOU KNEW ABOUT THAT?
EVERYONE DOES.
WHAT'S THAT STORY?
IT'S A LONG ONE,
AANG.
SOME OTHER TIME.
YOU AND DAD HAD
SO MANY HILARIOUS
ADVENTURES.
NOT ALL OF WHICH
WERE HILARIOUS
AT THE TIME,
BUT EVERYTHING'S
FUNNY WITH HINDSIGHT.
AANG!
PLEASE PUT THAT DOWN.
IT'S CEREMONIAL
AND VERY FRAGILE.
Sokka:
WAS IT YOU OR DAD
THAT PUT AN OCTOPUS
ON YOUR HEAD AND CONVINCED
GRAN-GRAN YOU WERE A WATER
SPIRIT?
YOUR DAD
WORE THE OCTOPUS,
BUT I DID
THE SPOOKY VOICE.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
Man: AAH! UNH.
[GRUNTING]
- OUT OF MY WAY!
STEP ASIDE, FILTH.
HE MEANS NO OFFENSE.
I'M CERTAIN
YOU BATHE REGULARLY.
I NEED TO TALK
TO YOU.
- WELL, IF IT ISN'T
MY NEW FRIENDS,
ANGRY BOY
AND UNCLE LAZY.
HEH HEH HEH!
[CHEERING]
YOUR BEAST
TRASHED MY SHIP.
YOU HAVE TO PAY ME BACK.
WELL, I'D LOVE
TO HELP YOU OUT,
BUT I'M A LITTLE SHORT
ON MONEY.
DRINKS ON ME!
[CHEERING AND SHOUTING]
MONEY ISN'T WHAT
I HAD IN MIND.
I NEED YOU TO
FIND SOMEONE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOUR GIRLFRIEND
RUN OFF ON YOU?
IT'S NOT THE GIRL
I'M AFTER.
IT'S THE BALD MONK
SHE'S TRAVELING WITH.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
IF YOU FIND THEM,
I'LL CONSIDER
THE DAMAGE TO MY SHIP
PAID FOR.
HA! FORGET IT.
PLUS WE'LL PAY
YOUR WEIGHT IN GOLD.
MAKE IT YOUR WEIGHT,
AND WE GOT A DEAL.
HA HA HA!
YOU GOT IT!
GET ON!
Bato: THERE'S SOMETHING
I SHOULD TELL YOU KIDS.
I'M EXPECTING A MESSAGE
FROM YOUR FATHER.
Katara: REALLY?
WHEN?
ANY DAY NOW.
YOUR FATHER SAID
HE'D SEND A MESSAGE
WHEN THEY FOUND
THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
IF YOU WAIT HERE
UNTIL THE MESSAGE ARRIVES,
YOU CAN COME WITH ME
AND SEE YOUR FATHER AGAIN.
IT'S BEEN
OVER TWO YEARS
SINCE WE'VE SEEN DAD.
THAT WOULD BE
SO INCREDIBLE.
KATARA!
Katara: I DO
REALLY MISS HIM.
IT WOULD BE GREAT
TO SEE DAD.
Bato: IT'S BEEN
FAR TOO LONG,
HASN'T IT?
I'M NOT SURE
WHEN WORD WILL ARRIVE,
BUT WHEN IT DOES...
IT WOULD BE GREAT,
BUT WE CAN'T.
WE HAVE TO TAKE AANG
TO THE NORTH POLE FIRST.
EVEN IF WE HAD TIME
TO WAIT FOR THE MESSAGE,
WHO KNOWS HOW FAR
WE'D HAVE TO TRAVEL?
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR A LONG DETOUR.
I'M SURE YOUR FATHER
WOULD UNDERSTAND
AND BE PROUD THAT HIS CHILDREN
ARE HELPING THE AVATAR.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY WOULD LEAVE ME.
[HORSE NEIGHING]
I'M LOOKING FOR BATO
OF THE WATER TRIBE.
UH, I KNOW BATO.
MAKE SURE HE GETS THIS.
IT'S THE MAP TO SOKKA
AND KATARA'S DAD.
HEY, EVERYONE.
SORRY I WAS GONE
SO LONG.
HEY, AANG.
I DIDN'T NOTICE
YOU LEFT.
YEP. BUT NOW I'M BACK.
SURE COULD GO FOR SOME
DELICIOUS SEA PRUNES.
MMM! YUM YUM! MMM!
[CHOKES]
MMM!
[ROAR]
OUT FOR A BIT OF
FRESH AIR, ARE WE?
Zuko: WE'RE LOOKING
FOR SOMEONE.
I HOPE
IT'S NOT MIYUKI.
MIYUKI, DID YOU
GET IN TROUBLE
WITH THE FIRE NATION
AGAIN?
[WHIMPER]
THE AVATAR'S
BEEN THROUGH HERE.
LET'S KEEP MOVING.
AHA! I CAUGHT YOU.
YOU SHOULD BE
ASHAMED OF YOURSELF.
LITTERING
IN THE COURTYARD.
I'M SORRY.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF THIS.
Bato: THIS SHIP
IS SENTIMENTAL TO ME.
IT WAS BUILT
BY MY FATHER.
[WHISTLING]
Sokka: IS THIS THE BOAT
HE TOOK YOU ICE DODGING IN?
Bato:
YEP, AND IT'S GOT
THE SCAR TO PROVE IT.
HA! HOW ABOUT YOU,
SOKKA?
YOU MUST HAVE
SOME GOOD STORIES
FROM YOUR FIRST TIME
ICE DODGING.
HE NEVER GOT TO GO.
DAD LEFT BEFORE
HE WAS OLD ENOUGH.
OH, I FORGOT.
YOU WERE TOO YOUNG.
WHAT'S ICE DODGING?
IT'S A RITE OF PASSAGE
FOR YOUNG WATER TRIBE
MEMBERS.
WHEN YOU TURN 14,
YOUR DAD TAKES YOU--
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE ABOUT
TO FIND OUT.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
Zuko:
WHY ARE WE STOPPING?
BECAUSE THE GIRL
MUST HAVE SPENT
A LOT OF TIME HERE.
WE HAVE NO TIME
FOR THIS.
HEY, WATCH IT!
HEH HEH HEH!
OH, LOOK.
HE LIKES YOU.
CARE TO HEAR
YOUR FORTUNE, HANDSOME?
AT MY AGE,
THERE'S REALLY ONLY
ONE BIG SURPRISE LEFT,
AND I'D JUST AS SOON
LEAVE IT A MYSTERY.
[SNARLING]
Bato: ICE DODGING
IS A CEREMONIAL TEST
OF WISDOM, BRAVERY,
AND TRUST.
IN OUR VILLAGE,
IT WAS DONE
BY WEAVING A BOAT
THROUGH A FIELD
OF ICEBERGS.
- HOW ARE WE SUPPOSED TO
ICE DODGE WITHOUT ICE?
YOU'LL BE DODGING...
THOSE.
SOKKA, YOU STEER
AND CALL THE SHOTS.
LEAD WISELY.
KATARA, YOU SECURE
THE MAINSAIL.
THE WINDS CAN BE BRUTAL.
SO BE BRAVE.
AANG, YOU CONTROL
THE JIB.
WITHOUT YOUR STEADY HAND,
WE ALL GO DOWN.
YOUR POSITION
IS ABOUT TRUST.
I KNOW THAT!
WHY WOULDN'T I
KNOW THAT?
I'M THE AVATAR!
I KNOW ABOUT TRUST.
FOR THIS TO BE DONE RIGHT,
I CANNOT HELP.
YOU PASS OR FAIL ON YOUR OWN.
AANG, EASE UP ON THE JIB.
KATARA, STEADY.
AANG, LESS SAIL.
UNH! KATARA, GIVE HIM ROOM.
UNH!
AANG, HELM TO LEE.
HELM TO LEE.
WHAT DOES THAT
EVEN MEAN?
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
GREAT JOB!
THERE'S NO WAY THROUGH!
WE CAN MAKE IT!
SOKKA, YOU'VE ALREADY
PROVEN YOURSELF.
MAYBE WE SHOULD--
AANG! I'M GONNA NEED AIR
IN THAT SAIL!
KATARA, I WANT YOU TO BEND
AS MUCH WATER AS YOU CAN
BETWEEN US AND THOSE ROCKS.
NOW!
[GROANS]
[SIGH]
THE SPIRITS OF WATER
BEAR WITNESS TO
THESE MARKS.
FOR SOKKA, THE MARK
OF THE WISE--
THE SAME MARK
YOUR FATHER EARNED.
FOR KATARA, THE MARK
OF THE BRAVE.
YOUR COURAGE
INSPIRES US.
AND FOR AANG, THE MARK
OF THE TRUSTED.
YOU ARE NOW
AN HONORARY MEMBER
OF THE WATER TRIBE.
I CAN'T.
OF COURSE YOU CAN.
NO. YOU CAN'T TRUST ME.
AANG, WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
A MESSENGER GAVE THIS
TO ME FOR BATO.
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND.
I WAS AFRAID YOU WOULDN'T--
THIS IS THE MAP
TO OUR FATHER!
YOU HAD IT
THE WHOLE TIME?
HOW COULD YOU?
WELL, YOU CAN GO
TO THE NORTH POLE
ON YOUR OWN.
I'M GOING
TO FIND DAD.
Bato: NOW, SOKKA,
I THINK YOU SHOULD--
KATARA,
ARE YOU WITH ME?
I'M WITH YOU,
SOKKA.
GOOD LUCK.
OK. YOU, TOO.
GUESS I SHOULD BE
MOVING ON.
THAT WOULD BE BEST.
I'M AN IDIOT, MOMO.
[FOOTSTEPS]
[ROARING]
WE'RE GETTING CLOSE.
[WOLF HOWLS]
THAT WOLF
SOUNDS SO SAD.
IT'S PROBABLY
WOUNDED.
NO. IT'S BEEN SEPARATED
FROM THE PACK.
I UNDERSTAND THAT PAIN.
IT'S HOW I FELT
WHEN THE WATER TRIBE WARRIORS
HAD TO LEAVE ME BEHIND.
THEY WERE MY FAMILY,
AND BEING APART FROM THEM
WAS MORE PAINFUL THAN MY WOUNDS.
SOKKA?
WE NEED TO GO BACK.
I WANT TO SEE DAD,
BUT HELPING AANG
IS WHERE WE'RE
NEEDED THE MOST.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOUR FATHER WILL UNDERSTAND,
AND I KNOW
HE'S PROUD OF YOU.
THANKS, BATO.
I KNOW WHERE TO GO
FROM HERE.
TAKE THIS IN CASE
YOU WANT TO FIND US.
I'LL LEAVE A MESSAGE
AT THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE
GOING ALONE, GUYS.
AVATAR!
YOU MUST LEAVE.
OK, I GET IT.
EVERYBODY WANTS ME GONE.
A GROUP OF PEOPLE
CAME TO THE ABBEY
LOOKING FOR YOU.
WHO?
A FIERCE-LOOKING
WOMAN WITH
A HORRIBLE MONSTER
AND A YOUNG MAN
WITH A SCAR.
ZUKO.
THE BEAST WAS USING
THE SCENT OF
THE NECKLACE TO FOLLOW YOU.
A NECKLACE?
[GASP]
KATARA!
[FOOTSTEPS]
[ROARING]
SO THIS IS
YOUR GIRLFRIEND.
NO WONDER SHE LEFT.
SHE'S WAY TOO PRETTY
FOR YOU.
WHERE IS HE?
WHERE'S THE AVATAR?
WE SPLIT UP.
HE'S LONG GONE.
HOW STUPID DO YOU THINK I AM?
PRETTY STUPID.
RUN!
Both: AAH! UNH!
Zuko: WHAT ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO DO NOW?
IT'S SEEKING
A DIFFERENT SCENT,
PERHAPS SOMETHING
THAT THE AVATAR HELD.
[SNIFFING]
[SCREAMING]
Zuko:
WHAT'S IT DOING?
IT'S JUST GOING
IN A CIRCLE.
[YELLING]
AANG!
UP!
HAH!
AARGH!
AAH!
UNH!
OOF!
COME ON, GET UP!
[GROWLING]
UNH!
[GRUNTS]
[GASP]
AAH!
I'M STARTING TO GET
SOME FEELING BACK.
OW.
[SNIFFS]
AHH.
YOU'VE GOT
SOMETHING I WANT.
AAH!
UNH!
OOF!
[SNIFF]
UGH.
THAT THING SEES
WITH ITS NOSE. LET'S GIVE HIM
SOMETHING TO LOOK AT.
THE PERFUME?
OHH!
JUNE, NO!
UNCLE?
I DIDN'T SEE YOU
GET HIT WITH THE TONGUE.
SHH.
SO...
WHERE DO WE GO?
WE'RE GETTING YOU
TO THE NORTH POLE.
YEAH. WE'VE LOST
TOO MUCH TIME
AS IT IS.
DON'T YOU WANT
TO SEE YOUR FATHER?
OF COURSE WE DO,
AANG,
BUT YOU'RE
OUR FAMILY, TOO,
AND RIGHT NOW,
YOU NEED US MORE.
AND WE NEED YOU.
I WISH I COULD GIVE YOU
A LITTLE PIECE OF HOME, KATARA,
SOMETHING TO REMIND YOU--
I'LL BE OK.
STILL, JUST A LITTLE TRINKET.
MAYBE SOMETHING LIKE...THIS?
AANG!
HOW'D YOU GET THAT?
ZUKO ASKED ME TO BE SURE
I GOT IT TO YOU.
OH, THAT'S SO SWEET
OF ZUKO.
WOULD YOU GIVE HIM
A KISS FOR ME
WHEN YOU SEE HIM?
SURE.
MWAH.
♪