Girl: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
Girl: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
I WANT TO SEE DAD,
BUT HELPING AANG
IS WHERE WE'RE
NEEDED THE MOST.
NEWS FROM FIRE LORD OZAI?
IT APPEARS I'VE BEEN
PROMOTED TO ADMIRAL.
THE HUNT FOR THE AVATAR
HAS BEEN GIVEN
PRIME IMPORTANCE.
AANG, YOU MUST DEFEAT
THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET ARRIVES.
YOU MUST DO IT
BY SUMMER'S END.
[COOING]
Katara: THIS SHOULD
GIVE US A GOOD IDEA
OF WHAT'S AROUND HERE.
SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND A MENU.
I'M STARVING.
Aang: I BET WE'LL FIND
SOMETHING TO EAT HERE--
THE FIRE DAYS FESTIVAL.
FIRE NATION
CULTURAL EXHIBITS,
JUGGLERS,
BENDERS, MAGICIANS...
THIS WOULD BE A GREAT
PLACE FOR ME
TO STUDY SOME
REAL FIREBENDERS.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO RETHINK THAT.
LOOK AT THIS.
Aang: HEY,
A POSTER OF ME!
A WANTED POSTER.
THIS IS BAD.
I THINK WE BETTER
KEEP MOVING.
I HAVE TO LEARN
FIREBENDING AT SOME POINT,
AND THIS COULD
BE MY ONLY CHANCE
TO WATCH SOME
MASTERS UP CLOSE.
I GUESS WE COULD
GO CHECK IT OUT.
Sokka: WHAT?!
YOU WANT TO WALK INTO
A FIRE NATION TOWN
WHEN THEY'RE
ALL FIRED UP
WITH ALL THEIR,
YOU KNOW, FIRE?
WE'LL WEAR DISGUISES.
AND IF IT LOOKS LIKE
TROUBLE, WE'LL LEAVE.
YEAH.
BECAUSE WE
ALWAYS LEAVE
BEFORE WE GET
INTO TROUBLE.
[GROWLING]
YOU GUYS STAY OUT
OF SIGHT HERE
WHILE WE GO
TO THE FESTIVAL.
[COOING]
READY DISGUISES.
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE A WHOLE
DIFFERENT PERSON.
LET'S GO!
HA HA HA HA!
Katara: I THINK WE
NEED SOME NEW DISGUISES.
WHERE ARE WE GONNA
GET MASKS LIKE THAT?
GET YOUR GENUINE
FIRE-FESTIVAL
MASKS HERE!
THAT WAS
SURPRISINGLY EASY.
HEY, THERE'S SOME FOOD.
FINALLY!
WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
FLAMING
FIRE FLAKES.
BEST IN TOWN.
I'LL TAKE 'EM.
MMM! MMM!
[SCREAMING]
OH, HOT, HOT!
FLAMING FIRE
FLAKES, HOT.
WHAT DO
YOU KNOW?
HEY, LOOK AT THIS!
DON'T WORRY,
LOYAL CITIZENS,
NO ONE CAN SURPRISE
THE FIRE LORD!
OH, NO!
LOOK OUT!
[CHEERING]
Katara: AANG, HOLD ON.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
I DON'T KNOW...
BUT THERE'S A BIG CROWD,
SO IT MUST BE GOOD.
Sokka: KNOWING
THE FIRE NATION,
IT'S PROBABLY AN EXECUTION.
[APPLAUSE]
I GOTTA LEARN THAT TRICK.
THANK YOU!
FOR MY NEXT TRICK,
I NEED A VOLUNTEER
FROM THE AUDIENCE.
OOH, OOH! ME! ME!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
I WANT TO GET
A CLOSER LOOK.
IT'S BETTER THAT
WE DON'T ATTRACT
ANY ATTENTION
TO OURSELVES.
HOW ABOUT YOU,
LITTLE LADY?
UH...
AW, SHE'S SHY.
LET'S GIVE HER SOME
ENCOURAGEMENT, FOLKS.
[CHEERING]
AW, THAT COULD
HAVE BEEN ME.
THIS NEXT TRICK
IS CALLED
TAMING THE DRAGON!
YOU WILL BE MY
CAPTURED PRINCESS.
DON'T WORRY,
YOUNG MAIDEN!
I WILL TAME
THIS FIERY BEAST!
IT'S TOO STRONG!
I CAN'T HOLD IT!
WE GOTTA HELP HER!
NO, WE DON'T WANT
TO MAKE A SCENE.
THE ROPE--IT'S BREAKING!
[SCREAMS]
HEY, YOU TRYING TO
UPSTAGE ME, KID?
[BOOING]
Man: HEY! THAT
KID'S THE AVATAR!
I THINK IT'S TIME TO GO.
Man: FOLLOW ME!
I CAN GET YOU
OUT OF HERE!
Guard: THERE THEY ARE!
OVER THERE!
I'M CALLING APPA.
Sokka: I HOPE
HE CAN REALLY HEAR
THAT BISON WHISTLE!
Man: THIS WAY!
OK, NOT THIS WAY.
[MEN COUGHING]
HUH?!
[GROWLS]
Aang: APPA, DOWN HERE!
[CHEERING]
BEAUTIFUL!
[LAUGHTER]
Aang: NICE TOUCH
SETTING OFF
THE FIREWORKS.
Sokka: YOU SEEM TO REALLY
KNOW YOUR EXPLOSIVES.
I'M FAMILIAR.
YOU'RE A FIRE NATION
SOLDIER.
WAS.
MY NAME'S CHEY.
Chey: I SERVE A MAN--
MORE THAN A MAN, REALLY,
HE'S A MYTH--
BUT HE'S REAL,
A LIVING LEGEND--
JEONG JEONG
THE DESERTER.
HE WAS A FIRE NATION
GENERAL.
OR WAIT...
WAS HE AN ADMIRAL?
HE WAS VERY
HIGHLY RANKED.
WE GET IT.
YEAH! WAY UP THERE!
BUT HE COULDN'T TAKE
THE MADNESS ANYMORE.
HE'S THE FIRST PERSON EVER
TO LEAVE THE ARMY AND LIVE.
I'M THE SECOND,
BUT YOU DON'T GET TO
BE A LEGEND FOR THAT.
IT'S OK, THOUGH.
JEONG JEONG'S
A FIREBENDING GENIUS.
SOME SAY HE'S MAD,
BUT HE'S NOT.
HE'S ENLIGHTENED.
YOU MEAN THERE'S
A FIREBENDER OUT HERE
WHO'S NOT WITH
THE FIRE LORD?
WE'VE GOTTA GO SEE HIM!
HE CAN TRAIN ME!
WE'RE NOT
GONNA GO FIND
SOME CRAZY
FIREBENDER.
Chey: HE'S NOT CRAZY!
HE'S A GENIUS!
AND HE'S
THE PERFECT PERSON
TO TRAIN THE AVATAR.
THAT'S WHY I FOLLOWED YOU
INTO THE FESTIVAL.
LOOK, THANKS
FOR THE HELP,
BUT WE'RE LEAVING
FOR THE NORTH POLE
IN THE MORNING.
SOKKA, THIS COULD
BE MY ONLY CHANCE
TO MEET
A FIREBENDING MASTER
WHO WOULD ACTUALLY
BE WILLING TO TEACH ME.
IT CAN'T HURT JUST
TO TALK TO HIM.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU SAID ABOUT
GOING TO
THE FESTIVAL!
WHY DOESN'T ANYONE
EVER LISTEN TO ME?!
[GASPS]
AAGH!
DON'T MOVE.
[LOWING]
Soldier: JEONG JEONG
TOLD YOU
NOT TO LOOK
FOR AVATAR.
HOLD ON.
YOU KNOW THESE GUYS?
OH, YEAH.
LIN YE'S
AN OLD BUDDY.
RIGHT, LIN YE?
SHUT UP.
KEEP MOVING.
[COOING]
Lin Ye: GO ON.
HE SEES YOU ONLY.
OH, THAT'S OK.
WE CAN CHAT LATER.
IS THAT WHERE
JEONG JEONG IS?
I NEED TO TALK
TO HIM RIGHT AWAY.
NO. YOU WAIT THERE.
GO, NOW!
DON'T WORRY.
EVERYTHING WILL BE FINE.
Chey: HE'S A GREAT MAN.
A GREAT MAN!
Zhao: SO, THE AVATAR
WAS HERE
AND YOU LET HIM SLIP AWAY?
YES, SIR.
BUT OTHER THAN THAT,
THE FESTIVAL WENT OFF
WITHOUT A HITCH.
[GRUNTS]
NO FIGHTS.
THEFT WAS WAY DOWN.
I DON'T CARE
ABOUT YOUR LOCAL
CRIME RATES!
WHICH WAY
DID THEY GO?
THEY HEADED INTO THE FOREST.
UP THE RIVER, I SUSPECT.
READY THE RIVERBOATS.
WE'RE GOING AFTER
THE AVATAR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
CAN I SEE
JEONG JEONG NOW?
HE WON'T SEE YOU.
HE'S VERY ANGRY THAT
I BROUGHT YOU HERE.
HE WANTS YOU TO
LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
FINALLY!
LET'S HIT THE ROAD.
WHY WON'T HE SEE ME?
HE SAYS YOU'RE
NOT READY.
SAYS YOU HAVEN'T
MASTERED
WATERBENDING
AND EARTHBENDING YET.
WAIT, HOW DOES
HE KNOW THAT?
HE SAW THE WAY
YOU WALKED INTO CAMP.
HE CAN TELL.
I'M GOING IN ANYWAY.
[INHALES]
GET OUT!
MASTER, I NEED TO
LEARN FIREBENDING.
ONLY A FOOL SEEKS
HIS OWN DESTRUCTION.
I AM THE AVATAR.
IT'S MY DESTINY TO--
DESTINY?
WHAT WOULD A BOY
KNOW OF DESTINY?
IF A FISH LIVES
ITS WHOLE LIFE
IN THIS RIVER,
DOES HE KNOW
THE RIVER'S DESTINY?
NO!
ONLY THAT IT RUNS
ON AND ON
OUT OF HIS CONTROL.
HE MAY FOLLOW
WHERE IT FLOWS,
BUT HE CANNOT SEE THE END.
HE CANNOT IMAGINE THE OCEAN.
OK...
BUT IT'S THE AVATAR'S DUTY
TO MASTER ALL OF
THE BENDING DISCIPLINES.
TO MASTER
THE BENDING DISCIPLINES,
YOU MUST FIRST MASTER
DISCIPLINE ITSELF.
BUT YOU HAVE
NO INTEREST IN THIS,
SO I HAVE NO INTEREST
IN YOU.
NOW, GET OUT.
PLEASE,
I HAVE TO LEARN.
THIS COULD BE
MY ONLY CHANCE.
ARE YOU DEAF?!
HOW CAN I TEACH YOU
IF YOU REFUSE TO LISTEN?!
BEFORE LEARNING
FIREBENDING,
YOU MUST LEARN
WATER AND EARTH.
WATER IS COOL AND SOOTHING.
EARTH IS STEADY AND STABLE.
BUT FIRE...
FIRE IS ALIVE.
IT BREATHES, IT GROWS.
WITHOUT THE BENDER, A ROCK
WILL NOW THROW ITSELF.
BUT FIRE WILL SPREAD
AND DESTROY EVERYTHING
IN ITS PATH
IF ONE DOES NOT HAVE
THE WILL TO CONTROL IT!
THAT IS ITS DESTINY.
YOU ARE NOT READY!
YOU ARE TOO WEAK!
YOU THINK I AM WEAK?
AVATAR ROKU!
NO, NO!
I DID NOT MEAN THAT.
I HAVE MASTERED
THE ELEMENTS
A THOUSAND TIMES
IN A THOUSAND LIFETIMES.
NOW, I MUST
DO IT ONCE AGAIN.
YOU WILL TEACH
THE AVATAR FIREBENDING.
YES, YES.
I WILL TEACH YOU.
Aang: REALLY?
THAT'S GREAT!
[GROANS]
WIDEN YOUR STANCE.
WIDER!
BEND YOUR KNEES.
NOW, CONCENTRATE.
GOOD. GOOD!
WAIT.
WHAT DO I DO NOW?
SILENCE!
TALKING IS NOT
CONCENTRATING.
LOOK AT YOUR FRIEND.
IS SHE TALKING?
EVEN THAT OAF KNOWS
TO CONCENTRATE
ON WHAT HE'S DOING.
Sokka: HEY!
BUT WHAT AM I
CONCENTRATING ON?
FEEL THE HEAT OF THE SUN.
IT IS THE GREATEST
SOURCE OF FIRE,
YET IT IS IN COMPLETE
BALANCE WITH NATURE.
SO, WHEN DO I GET
TO MAKE SOME FIRE?
CONCENTRATE!
[SIGHS]
[LAUGHTER]
Aang: ARE WE
COMING UP HERE
SO I DON'T
BURN ANYTHING
WITH MY FIRE BLASTS?
NO FIRE YET.
WHAT?!
POWER IN FIREBENDING
COMES FROM
THE BREATH.
THAT IS WHY
YOU MUST MASTER
PROPER
BREATH CONTROL.
YOU BROUGHT ME
UP HERE TO BREATHE?
ASSUME YOUR STANCE.
WIDER.
YOU'RE NOT
EVEN LOOK--
WIDER!
NOW, INHALE
THROUGH THE NOSE
AND EXHALE THROUGH
THE MOUTH--
WITHOUT TALKING.
[INHALES]
[EXHALES]
GOOD.
KEEP GOING.
[INHALES]
[EXHALES]
Jeong Jeong:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I DID NOT TELL
YOU TO STOP!
I'VE BEEN
BREATHING FOR HOURS.
YOU WANT TO
STOP BREATHING?
I WANT YOU TO STOP
WASTING MY TIME.
I ALREADY KNOW HOW
TO SQUAT AND BREATHE
AND FEEL THE SUN.
I WANT TO KNOW
HOW TO SHOOT FIRE
OUT OF MY FINGERTIPS.
[SIGHS]
I HAD A PUPIL ONCE
WHO HAD NO INTEREST
IN LEARNING DISCIPLINE.
HE WAS ONLY CONCERNED
WITH THE POWER OF FIRE--
HOW HE COULD USE IT
TO DESTROY HIS OPPONENTS
AND WIPE OUT
THE OBSTACLES IN HIS PATH,
BUT FIRE IS A HORRIBLE
BURDEN TO BEAR.
IT'S NATURE IS TO CONSUME,
AND WITHOUT CONTROL, IT DESTROYS
EVERYTHING AROUND IT.
[GRUNTS]
Jeong Jeong:
LEARN RESTRAINT,
OR RISK
DESTROYING YOURSELF
AND EVERYTHING
YOU LOVE.
I THOUGHT
ABOUT WHAT SAID.
I PROMISE I'LL
BE MORE PATIENT.
WE'RE GOING TO WORK
WITH FIRE NOW.
OH, YEAH!
I MEAN...
LET US BEGIN.
CONCENTRATE ON THE FIRE.
I WANT YOU TO
KEEP THIS FLAME
FROM REACHING
THE EDGES OF THE LEAF
FOR AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
[GROANS]
Guard: MASTER,
THERE IS TROUBLE!
WHAT'S GOING ON?!
CONCENTRATE
ON YOUR LEAF.
THIS IS
THE WORST
FIREBENDING
INSTRUCTION EVER.
ALL HE DOES IS LEAVE
ME ALONE FOR HOURS
TO CONCENTRATE
OR BREATHE.
I'M SURE THERE'S
A GOOD REASON.
BUT I'M READY
TO DO SO MUCH MORE.
[EXHALES]
[INHALES]
I DID IT.
I MADE FIRE!
AANG, THAT'S GREAT.
BUT YOU SHOULD
TAKE IT SLOW.
WHOA!
CAREFUL!
AAGH!
NOW,
THAT'S FIREBENDING.
AANG, YOU'LL HURT YOURSELF.
I WONDER HOW THAT
JUGGLER DID IT.
[SCREAMS]
KATARA!
I'M SO SORRY!
[WEEPING]
KATARA,
WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT!
I WAS--UH!
KATARA, I'M SO--
[GRUNTS]
I TOLD YOU WE SHOULDN'T
MESS AROUND WITH THIS!
LOOK WHAT YOU DID!
YOU BURNED MY SISTER!
[SOBBING]
THIS IS ALL YOUR FAULT!
I KNOW!
NOW, PACK YOUR THINGS.
YOU MUST LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T--
I'M SORRY!
[WEEPING]
[GRUNTING]
Jeong Jeong: YOU HAVE
HEALING ABILITIES.
THE GREAT BENDERS
OF THE WATER TRIBES
SOMETIMES HAVE
THIS ABILITY.
I'VE ALWAYS WISHED I
WERE BLESSED LIKE YOU--
FREE FROM THIS
BURNING CURSE.
BUT YOU'RE A GREAT MASTER.
YOU HAVE POWERS
I'LL NEVER KNOW.
WATER BRINGS
HEALING AND LIFE.
BUT FIRE BRINGS
ONLY DESTRUCTION
AND PAIN.
IT FORCES THOSE OF US
BURDENED WITH ITS CARE
TO WALK A RAZOR'S EDGE
BETWEEN HUMANITY
AND SAVAGERY.
EVENTUALLY WE'RE TORN APART.
GO GET YOUR
FRIENDS AND FLEE!
DO NOT COME BACK HERE
OR YOU WILL ALL
BE DESTROYED!
HURRY!
DON'T WORRY, MEN.
MY OLD TEACHER
GAVE UP FIGHTING
A LONG TIME AGO...
HAVEN'T YOU,
MASTER JEONG JEONG?
KATARA, ARE
YOU ALL RIGHT?!
I'M FINE.
WE'VE GOTTA
GET OUT OF HERE.
WHERE'S AANG?
JEONG JEONG TRIED TO
TELL ME
THAT I WASN'T READY.
I WOULDN'T LISTEN.
I'M NEVER GONNA
FIREBEND AGAIN.
Katara: YOU'LL
HAVE TO EVENTUALLY.
NO, NEVER AGAIN.
IT'S OK, AANG.
I'M HEALED.
WHAT? HOW?!
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
BUT, RIGHT NOW, WE HAVE
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
ZHAO AND HIS SOLDIERS
ARE ATTACKING.
WHERE?!
BY THE RIVER.
THEY CAPTURED JEONG JEONG.
I HAVE TO HELP HIM!
Zhao: LOOK AT YOU.
YOU WERE ONCE SO GREAT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
MY FORMER MASTER
HAS BECOME NOTHING MORE
THAN A SIMPLE SAVAGE.
IT IS YOU WHO HAVE
EMBRACED SAVAGERY, ZHAO.
IT'S ADMIRAL ZHAO NOW.
THAT TITLE WILL
NOT HELP YOU
AGAINST THE AVATAR.
DO NOT TRY TO
FIGHT HIM.
YOU ARE NO MATCH.
I THINK I CAN
HANDLE A CHILD.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN
SUCH RAW POWER.
[GROWLS]
Aang: JEONG JEONG!
WE'LL SEE.
MEN, TAKE THE DESERTER.
Zhao: IT'S A TRICK!
HE'S RUN OFF INTO THE WOODS.
FIND HIM!
LET'S FIND OUT WHAT MY
OLD MASTER HAS TAUGHT YOU.
YOU WERE JEONG JEONG'S
STUDENT?
UNTIL I GOT BORED.
[GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
I SEE HE TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO DUCK AND RUN
LIKE A COWARD,
BUT I DOUBT
HE SHOWED YOU WHAT
A FIREBENDER
IS TRULY CAPABLE OF!
[GROWLS]
WHOA! WILD SHOT!
I'LL SHOW YOU WILD!
[GRUNTS]
NO SELF-CONTROL.
Zhao: STAND
AND FIGHT, AVATAR!
OH, WERE WE FIGHTING?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
JUST GETTING WARMED UP.
I WAS.
IS THAT ALL YOU GOT?
MAN, THEY'LL MAKE ANYONE
AN ADMIRAL THESE DAYS.
[GROWLING]
AHOY!
I'M ADMIRAL ZHAO.
[GROWLS]
I DON'T KNOW WHY,
BUT I THOUGHT YOU'D
BE BETTER THAN ZUKO.
AAGH!
SLOPPY.
VERY SLOPPY.
[GRUNTS]
NOWHERE TO RUN NOW,
YOU LITTLE SMART MOUTH.
YOU'VE LOST THIS BATTLE.
ARE YOU CRAZY?!
YOU HAVEN'T THROWN
A SINGLE BLOW.
NO, BUT YOU HAVE.
JEONG JEONG SAID YOU
HAD NO RESTRAINT.
[SCREAMS]
HAVE A NICE WALK HOME!
Sokka: AANG, COME ON!
LET'S GO!
WAIT! WHERE'S JEONG JEONG?
HE DISAPPEARED.
THEY ALL DID.
HEY, WHERE'D EVERYBODY GO?
VERY FUNNY, GUYS!
[LOWING]
AANG, YOU'RE BURNED.
LET ME HELP YOU.
[INHALES]
[EXHALES]
WOW! THAT'S GOOD WATER.
WHEN DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO DO THAT?
I GUESS I ALWAYS KNEW.
OH. WELL, THEN,
THANKS FOR ALL
THE FIRST AID
OVER THE YEARS--
LIKE, WHEN I FELL INTO
THE GREASEBERRY BRAMBLE,
AND THAT TIME I HAD
TWO FISHHOOKS IN MY THUMB!
TWO?
HE TRIED TO GET
THE FIRST FISHHOOK OUT
WITH ANOTHER FISHHOOK.
Sokka: OH, AND THE TIME
THAT MING SNAKE BIT ME.
THANKS FOR HEALING THAT UP.
THAT'S GREAT.
REALLY HELPFUL.
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]