Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Aang: THERE IT IS--
THE SOUTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
THIS PLACE USED TO
BE FULL OF MONKS
AND LEMURS AND BISON.
I CAN'T BELIEVE HOW MUCH
THINGS HAVE CHANGED.
[GRUNTING]
I DON'T SUPPOSE
YOU HAVE A KEY?
THE KEY, SOKKA,
IS AIRBENDING.
AND IF FIREBENDERS
FOUND THIS TEMPLE,
THAT MEANS THEY FOUND
THE OTHER ONES, TOO.
I REALLY AM
THE LAST AIRBENDER.
Man: SO, TRAVELLERS, THE NEXT
TIME YOU THINK YOU HEAR
A STRANGE LARGE BIRD TALKING,
TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
IT MIGHT NOT BE A GIANT
PARROT, BUT A FLYING MAN,
A MEMBER OF A SECRET GROUP OF
AIRWALKERS WHO LAUGH AT GRAVITY
AND LAUGH AT THOSE BOUND
TO THE EARTH BY IT.
[MOMO COOING]
Aang: AREN'T AIRBENDER
STORIES THE BEST?
Katara: WAS IT
REALISTIC? IS THAT
HOW IT WAS BACK THEN?
I LAUGH AT GRAVITY
ALL THE TIME.
HA HA! GRAVITY.
JINGLE, JINGLE.
SORRY.
AW. CHEAPSKATES.
HEY, THANKS
FOR THE STORY.
TELL IT TO THE CAP, BOY.
AW. MUCH OBLIGED,
LITTLE BAT THING.
IT MEANS
A LOT TO HEAR
AIRBENDER STORIES.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO
YOUR GREAT-GRANDPA
MET THEM.
WHAT ARE YOU
PRATTLING ABOUT, CHILD?
GREAT-GRANDPAPPY SAW
THE AIRWALKERS LAST WEEK.
[GREAT-GRANDPA
SPEAKS HOARSELY]
Aang: WE'RE ALMOST
TO THE NORTHERN
AIR TEMPLE.
THIS IS
WHERE THEY HAD
THE CHAMPIONSHIPS
FOR SKY BISON POLO.
DO YOU THINK WE'LL
REALLY FIND AIRBENDERS?
YOU WANT ME TO BE LIKE
YOU OR TOTALLY HONEST?
ARE YOU SAYING
I'M A LIAR?
I'M SAYING
YOU'RE AN OPTIMIST.
SAME THING, BASICALLY.
HEY, GUYS, LOOK
AT THIS!
THEY REALLY ARE
AIRBENDERS!
NO, THEY'RE NOT.
WHAT
DO YOU MEAN,
THEY'RE NOT?
THOSE GUYS
ARE FLYING!
GLIDING MAYBE,
BUT NOT FLYING.
YOU CAN TELL BY
THE WAY THEY MOVE
THEY'RE NOT AIRBENDING.
THOSE PEOPLE HAVE NO SPIRIT.
OH!
[BOY CHUCKLING]
I DON'T KNOW, AANG.
THAT KID SEEMED
PRETTY SPIRITED.
OW!
WE'D BETTER FIND
SOME SOLID GROUND
BEFORE IT FINDS US.
HA HA!
GO, TEO!
SHOW THAT BALD KID
HOW IT'S DONE!
HEY THERE.
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD.
YEAH, I KNOW.
BUT I CAN DO MORE
THAN FANCY GLIDING.
WOW! I DON'T THINK
I CAN DO THAT.
BUT HERE'S A GOOD ONE.
[KIDS CHEERING]
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
[DEADPAN]
IT'S GREAT.
HEY, YOU'RE
A REAL AIRBENDER.
YOU MUST BE THE AVATAR.
THAT'S AMAZING!
I'VE HEARD STORIES
ABOUT YOU.
THANKS.
WOW! THIS
GLIDER CHAIR
IS INCREDIBLE.
IF YOU THINK
THIS IS GOOD,
WAIT UNTIL YOU SEE
THE OTHER STUFF
MY DAD DESIGNED.
WOW!
YEAH, MY
DAD IS THE
MASTERMIND
BEHIND THIS
WHOLE PLACE.
EVERYTHING
IS POWERED
BY HOT AIR.
IT EVEN PUMPS
HOT AIR CURRENTS OUTSIDE
TO GIVE US A LIFT
WHEN WE'RE GLIDING.
THIS PLACE IS UNBELIEVABLE.
YEAH. IT'S GREAT,
ISN'T IT?
Aang: NO. JUST
UNBELIEVABLE.
AANG USED TO COME HERE
A LONG TIME AGO.
I THINK HE'S A LITTLE
SHOCKED IT'S SO DIFFERENT.
SO BETTER!
Aang: THIS IS SUPPOSED
TO BE THE HISTORY
OF MY PEOPLE.
UGH!
I'M SURE SOME PARTS
OF THE TEMPLE
ARE STILL THE SAME.
Aang: IT'S NICE TO SEE
AT LEAST ONE PART
OF THE TEMPLE
THAT ISN'T RUINED.
[MAN YELLS]
[ALL COUGHING]
WHAT THE DOODLE?!
DON'T YOU
KNOW ENOUGH
TO STAY AWAY FROM
CONSTRUCTION SITES?
WE HAVE TO MAKE ROOM
FOR THE BATHHOUSE.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU DID?
YOU JUST DESTROYED
SOMETHING SACRED
FOR A STUPID BATHHOUSE.
WELL, PEOPLE AROUND HERE
ARE STARTING TO STINK.
THIS WHOLE PLACE STINKS.
HYAH!
THIS IS A SACRED TEMPLE.
YOU CAN'T TREAT IT THIS WAY.
I'VE SEEN IT WHEN
THE MONKS WERE HERE.
I KNOW WHAT IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE LIKE.
THE MONKS?
BUT YOU'RE 12.
DAD, HE'S THE AVATAR.
HE USED TO COME HERE
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO SAID YOU COULD BE HERE?
DOING HERE...
A LONG TIME AGO,
BUT NOT A HUNDRED YEARS,
MY PEOPLE BECAME
REFUGEES
AFTER A TERRIBLE
FLOOD.
MY INFANT SON,
TEO, WAS
BADLY HURT
AND LOST
HIS MOTHER.
[SNIFFLES]
I NEEDED SOMEWHERE
TO REBUILD,
AND I STUMBLED
ACROSS THIS PLACE.
COULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
EVERYWHERE PICTURES
OF FLYING PEOPLE,
BUT EMPTY.
NOBODY HOME.
THEN I CAME ACROSS
THESE FAN-LIKE CONTRAPTIONS.
OUR GLIDERS.
YES, LITTLE LIGHT
FLYING MACHINES.
THEY GAVE ME AN IDEA--
BUILD A NEW LIFE
FOR MY SON IN THE AIR.
THEN EVERYONE WOULD BE
ON EQUAL GROUND,
SO TO SPEAK.
WE'RE JUST IN
THE PROCESS OF IMPROVING
UPON WHAT'S ALREADY HERE.
AND AFTER ALL, ISN'T
THAT WHAT NATURE DOES?
Aang: NATURE KNOWS
WHERE TO STOP.
I SUPPOSE THAT'S TRUE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
PROGRESS HAS A WAY OF
GETTING AWAY FROM US.
LOOK AT THE TIME!
COME. THE PULLEY SYSTEM
MUST BE OILED BEFORE DARK.
WAIT. HOW CAN YOU
TELL THE TIME
FROM THAT THING?
THE NOTCHES
ALL LOOK THE SAME.
THE CANDLE WILL
TELL US. WATCH.
YOU PUT SPARK POWDER
IN THE CANDLE!
4 FLASHES.
SO IT'S EXACTLY
4 HOURS PAST MIDDAY,
OR AS I CALL IT,
4 O'CANDLE.
HA HA!
IF YOU LIKED THAT,
WAIT TILL YOU SEE
MY FINGER-SAFE
KNIFE SHARPENER.
IT ONLY TOOK ME 3 TRIES
TO GET IT RIGHT.
AAH!
Dad: FOLLOW ME.
HEY, AANG, I WANT TO SHOW
YOU SOMETHING.
Aang: I JUST CAN'T
GET OVER IT.
THERE'S NOT A SINGLE
THING THAT'S THE SAME.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THAT.
THE TEMPLE MIGHT
BE DIFFERENT,
BUT THE CREATURES
THAT LIVE HERE ARE
PROBABLY DIRECT
DESCENDANTS
OF THE ONES
THAT LIVED HERE
A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THEY'RE KIND OF KEEPERS
OF THE TEMPLE'S ORIGINS.
BESIDES, THERE
IS ONE PART
OF THE TEMPLE
THAT HASN'T
CHANGED AT ALL.
Katara: HEY...
IT'S JUST
LIKE THE ONE IN
THE OTHER AIR TEMPLE.
ONLY
AN AIRBENDER
CAN OPEN IT.
SO INSIDE,
IT'S COMPLETELY
UNTOUCHED.
JUST THE WAY
THE MONKS
LEFT IT.
I'VE ALWAYS
WONDERED WHAT IT
WAS LIKE IN THERE.
AANG?
I'M SORRY. THIS
IS THE LAST PART
OF THE TEMPLE
THAT'S THE SAME AS IT WAS.
I WANT IT TO STAY THAT WAY.
I COMPLETELY
UNDERSTAND.
I JUST WANTED YOU
TO KNOW IT WAS HERE.
THANKS.
THESE LANTERNS ARE
TERRIBLE. I CAN'T SEE.
WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO USE
FIREFLIES FOR LIGHT?
HEY! CLOSE THAT UP.
THEY'LL GET LOOSE.
FIREFLIES ARE
A NONFLAMMABLE
LIGHT SOURCE.
COVER YOUR NOSE
AND HOLD YOUR BREATH.
OK. SO YOU BROUGHT ME
ALL THE WAY DOWN HERE
TO SEE AN EMPTY ROOM.
WRONG.
IT'S FILLED TO THE BRIM
WITH NATURAL GAS.
I CAME ACROSS IT
MY FIRST TIME HERE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
I WAS CARRYING
A TORCH AT THE TIME.
NEARLY BLEW MYSELF
AND THE WHOLE PLACE
EVEN MORE SKY-HIGH.
I THOUGHT MY EYEBROWS
WOULD NEVER GROW BACK.
ANYWAY, THERE'S A VITAL
PROBLEM THAT NEEDS SOLVING.
FROM TIME TO TIME,
WE HAVE GAS LEAKS.
AND THEY'RE NEARLY
IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND.
SO THIS PLACE IS
AN EXPLOSION
WAITING TO HAPPEN.
YES. UNTIL I FIGURE
OUT HOW TO LOCATE
SOMETHING I CAN'T SEE,
HEAR, SMELL, OR TOUCH.
Teo: THE WIND
WILL CARRY YOU.
IT SUPPORTS SOMETHING
INSIDE YOU,
SOMETHING EVEN
LIGHTER THAN AIR.
AND THAT SOMETHING
TAKES OVER
WHEN YOU FLY.
I'VE CHANGED MY MIND.
I THINK I WAS BORN
WITHOUT THAT SOMETHING.
HA HA! IMPOSSIBLE.
EVERYBODY HAS IT.
Aang: SPIRIT.
WHAT?
THAT'S THE SOMETHING
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
YEAH. I SUPPOSE
IT IS.
ARE YOU READY?
NO! AAH!
[LAUGHING]
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M FLYING!
JUST MAKE SURE YOU
KEEP YOUR MOUTH CLOSED
SO YOU DON'T SWALLOW
A BUG.
TEO WAS RIGHT
ABOUT THE AIR.
ALL I HAD TO DO
WAS TRUST IT,
LET IT CARRY ME.
EVEN THOUGH TEO'S
NOT AN AIRBENDER,
HE REALLY DOES HAVE
THE SPIRIT OF ONE.
I'VE BEEN THINKING.
IF YOU WANT TO SEE
WHAT'S IN THAT ROOM,
I'D BE HAPPY TO OPEN
THE DOOR FOR YOU.
GREAT.
Katara: WAIT!
HOW DO I LAND THIS THING?
WHAT IF I LAND
OVER IN THE--
[GAGS]
BLECH! BUG. BUG.
THAT WAS A BUG.
[CRASH]
I SAID, DON'T
TOUCH ANYTHING.
OH!
OH, DON'T WORRY.
THAT EXPERIMENT IS OLD,
AND THAT EGG WAS JUST
PART OF LAST WEEK'S LUNCH.
[SNIFFS]
UGH!
WEEK-OLD EGG SMELL.
QUICK,
FIND THAT EGG.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I'M FINALLY GOING
TO SEE WHAT'S INSIDE.
HOW COULD SOMETHING
THAT'S SO SMALL,
YOU CAN'T EVEN SEE IT,
MAKE SUCH
A BIG STINK?
THAT'S THE SOLUTION
TO OUR PROBLEM.
YEAH. IF WE PUT A WHOLE
MESS OF ROTTEN EGGS
IN THE CELLAR WHERE
THE GAS SEEPS UP...
THE GAS WILL MIX WITH
THE SMELL OF ROTTEN EGGS.
THEN IF
THERE'S A LEAK...
YOU SMELL ROTTEN EGGS.
THEN YOU JUST
FOLLOW YOUR NOSE
TO THE PLACE WHERE
THE SMELL IS COMING FROM...
AND PLUG UP THE HOLE
WHERE THE GAS
IS ESCAPING.
YOU'RE A GENIUS!
YOU'RE
A GENIUS!
[BELL RINGING]
SOMETHING IS WRONG.
I'VE GOT TO GO.
THIS IS A NIGHTMARE.
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE MAKING WEAPONS
FOR THE FIRE NATION.
YOU MAKE WEAPONS
FOR THE FIRE NATION?
EXPLAIN
ALL THIS...NOW!
IT WAS ABOUT A YEAR
AFTER WE MOVED HERE.
FIRE NATION SOLDIERS
FOUND OUR SETTLEMENT.
YOU WERE TOO YOUNG
TO REMEMBER THIS TEO.
THEY WERE GOING
TO DESTROY EVERYTHING,
BURN IT TO THE GROUND.
I PLEADED WITH THEM.
I BEGGED THEM TO SPARE US.
THEY ASKED
WHAT I HAD TO OFFER.
I OFFERED MY SERVICES.
YOU MUST UNDERSTAND.
I DID THIS FOR YOU.
[DOOR OPENS]
WHEN ARE
THEY COMING?
SOON, VERY SOON.
YOU CAN'T GIVE THEM
MORE WEAPONS.
IF I DON'T GIVE THEM
WHAT THEY WANT,
THEY WILL
DESTROY THIS PLACE.
HOW CAN I BE
PROUD OF YOU
WHEN YOUR INVENTIONS
ARE BEING USED FOR MURDER?
I NEED SOME TIME
TO THINK.
[BELL RINGING]
YOU NEED TO LEAVE. GO.
WE'RE
NOT LEAVING.
THEN HIDE QUICKLY.
YOU KNOW BETTER THAN
TO KEEP ME WAITING.
GIVE ME WHAT YOU OWE US
SO I CAN BE ON MY WAY.
WELL?
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
NO. RIGHT THIS WAY.
THE DEAL IS OFF.
THE AVATAR.
AANG, DON'T GET INVOLVED.
IF I DON'T GET
WHAT I CAME FOR,
THE FIRE NATION
WILL BURN THIS
PLACE TO RUBBLE.
GET OUT OF HERE.
UH!
YOU'RE LEAVING
EMPTY-HANDED.
THEN THE DESTRUCTION
OF THIS TEMPLE WILL
BE ON YOUR HEAD.
THIS IS BAD,
VERY BAD.
AANG, WHAT
ARE WE GONNA DO?
HOW CAN WE POSSIBLY
KEEP THEM ALL AWAY?
I'LL TELL YOU HOW.
WE HAVE SOMETHING
THEY DON'T--
AIR POWER.
WE CONTROL THE SKY.
THAT'S SOMETHING
THE FIRE NATION
CAN'T DO.
WE CAN WIN.
Dad: I WANT
TO HELP.
GOOD.
WE'LL NEED IT.
WE FINALLY GOT
THE WAR BALLOON WORKING,
THANKS TO SOKKA.
THIS BOY
IS A GENIUS.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
SEE, THE PROBLEM
WITH THE OLD WAR BALLOON
WAS, YOU COULD
GET IT AIRBORNE,
BUT ONCE YOU DID,
IT JUST KEPT GOING.
YOU COULD PUT
A HOLE IN THE TOP,
BUT THEN ALL THE HOT AIR
WOULD ESCAPE.
SO THE QUESTION BECAME,
HOW DO YOU KEEP A LID
ON HOT AIR?
UGH.
IF ONLY WE KNEW.
[LAUGHTER]
A LID IS ACTUALLY
THE ANSWER.
IF YOU CONTROL THE HOT AIR,
YOU CONTROL THE WAR BALLOON.
HMM, THAT'S ACTUALLY
PRETTY SMART.
OK. WE GOT 4 KINDS
OF BOMBS--
SMOKE, SLIME,
FIRE, AND...
STINK.
NEVER UNDERESTIMATE
THE POWER OF STINK.
THEY'RE COMING!
ARE WE READY?
YES, BUT WHERE'S SOKKA
WITH THE WAR BALLOON?
WE'LL HAVE TO START
WITHOUT IT.
[CHEERING]
UHH!
UH!
OOH!
TAKE THEM
OUT OF THE SKY NOW!
[ALL COUGHING]
WE'VE GOT THEM
ON THE RUN.
WE NEED MORE SLIME.
AAH!
HUH!
UHH...UH!
WHOA!
UH! HUH!
UH! HUH! YAAH!
THOSE THINGS
ARE UNSTOPPABLE.
I THINK I KNOW
HOW THEY WORK.
I REMEMBER MY DAD TINKERING
WITH A COUNTERBALANCING SYSTEM,
SOMETHING TO DO WITH WATER.
WORKS GREAT, HUH?
WATER?
CAN YOU GET ME
CLOSE TO ONE?
NO PROBLEM.
HUH!
[ROAR]
WE'RE OUT OF BOMBS.
COME ON, SOKKA.
WHERE'S THAT WAR BALLOON?
HEY, WHY AREN'T THEY
SHOOTING AT US?
THE INSIGNIA.
THEY THINK
WE'RE ON THEIR SIDE.
THEN I GUESS THEY
WON'T SEE THIS COMING.
BOMBS AWAY.
UH!
HEY!
AAH!
OH, NO.
THAT WAS THE LAST ONE.
WAIT A SECOND.
[SNIFFS]
YOU SMELL THAT?
ROTTEN EGGS. THERE.
THAT'S WHERE
THE GAS IS ESCAPING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THAT'S OUR FUEL SOURCE.
IT'S THE ONLY BOMB
WE'VE GOT.
Aang: LOOK.
THEY'RE RETREATING.
YEAH!
Sokka:
WE'RE GOING DOWN!
NO!
SOKKA, HOLD ON!
GET READY.
OHHHH!
Aang: YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M REALLY GLAD YOU GUYS
ALL LIVE HERE NOW.
I REALIZED IT'S LIKE
THE HERMIT CRAB.
MAYBE YOU
WEREN'T BORN HERE,
BUT YOU FOUND
THIS EMPTY SHELL
AND MADE IT YOUR HOME,
AND NOW YOU
PROTECT EACH OTHER.
THAT MEANS A LOT
COMING FROM YOU.
AANG, YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT AIR POWER.
AS LONG AS WE'VE
GOT THE SKIES,
WE'LL HAVE
THE FIRE NATION
ON THE RUN.
[CHEERING]
THIS DEFEAT IS THE GATEWAY
TO MANY VICTORIES.
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]