Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
WELL, IF WE GO
TO THE NORTH POLE,
YOU CAN MASTER
WATERBENDING.
WE CAN LEARN IT TOGETHER!
Jeong Jeong: YOU HAVE
HEALING ABILITIES.
THE GREAT BENDERS
OF THE WATER TRIBE
SOMETIMES HAVE THIS ABILITY.
ALL INFORMATION
REGARDING THE AVATAR MUST BE
REPORTED DIRECTLY TO ADMIRAL
ZHAO.
WITH ZHAO'S RESOURCES,
IT'S JUST A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE HE CATCHES THE AVATAR.
MY HONOR,
MY THRONE, MY COUNTRY,
I'M ABOUT TO LOSE
THEM ALL.
[COOING]
[LOWING]
I'M NOT ONE
TO COMPLAIN,
BUT CAN'T APPA
FLY ANY HIGHER?
I HAVE AN IDEA.
WHY DON'T WE ALL
GET ON YOUR BACK,
AND YOU CAN FLY US
TO THE NORTH POLE.
I'D LOVE TO.
CLIMB ON, EVERYONE.
SOKKA IS READY
FOR TAKEOFF.
LOOK, WE'RE ALL JUST
A LITTLE TIRED AND CRANKY
BECAUSE WE'VE BEEN FLYING
FOR TWO DAYS STRAIGHT.
AND FOR WHAT?
WE CAN'T EVEN FIND
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
THERE'S NOTHING UP HERE.
[SPLASH]
AAGH!
[KIDS SCREAMING]
THEY'RE WATER BENDERS.
WE FOUND THE WATER TRIBE.
Zhao: HE'S HEADING NORTH.
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
THE AVATAR NEEDS TO
MASTER WATERBENDING.
HE LOOKING
FOR A TEACHER.
THEN WHAT ARE
WE WAITING FOR?
LET'S GO GET HIM.
PATIENCE, CAPTAIN LI.
THIS ISN'T SOME LITTLE
EARTH VILLAGE
WE CAN JUST MARCH INTO.
THE WATER TRIBE
IS A GREAT NATION.
THERE'S A REASON
THEY'VE SURVIVED
100 YEARS OF WAR.
THE FROZEN TUNDRA
IS TREACHEROUS.
THE LANDSCAPE ITSELF
IS AN ICY FORTRESS.
WE'LL NEED A MASSIVE
INVASION FORCE.
Aang: THERE IT IS!
Katara: THE NORTHERN
WATER TRIBE.
WE'RE FINALLY HERE.
[MOMO COOS]
Katara: I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW MANY WATERBENDERS
LIVE UP HERE.
WE'LL FIND A MASTER
TO TEACH US NO PROBLEM.
Katara: THIS PLACE
IS BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH.
SHE IS.
[STRINGED INSTRUMENT
PLAYING]
♪ WINTER, SPRING ♪
♪ SUMMER AND FALL ♪
♪ FOUR SEASONS ♪
♪ FOUR LOVES ♪
♪ FOR LOVE ♪
[MUSIC STOPS]
[DRUMS BEATING]
[SCREAMS]
TONIGHT, WE CELEBRATE
THE ARRIVAL
OF OUR BROTHER AND SISTER
FROM THE SOUTHERN TRIBE.
AND THEY HAVE BROUGHT WITH
THEM SOMEONE VERY SPECIAL,
SOMEONE WHO MANY
OF US BELIEVED
DISAPPEARED FROM
THE WORLD UNTIL NOW...
THE AVATAR.
[CHEERING]
WE ALSO CELEBRATE
MY DAUGHTER'S 16th BIRTHDAY.
PRINCESS YUE IS NOW
OF MARRYING AGE.
THANK YOU,
FATHER.
MAY THE GREAT OCEAN
AND MOON SPIRITS
WATCH OVER US DURING
THESE TROUBLED TIMES.
NOW, MASTER PAKKU AND HIS
STUDENTS WILL PERFORM!
[APPLAUSE]
HI THERE.
SOKKA, SOUTHERN
WATER TRIBE.
VERY NICE
TO MEET YOU.
SO, UH...
YOU'RE A PRINCESS, HUH?!
YOU KNOW,
BACK IN MY TRIBE,
I'M KIND OF LIKE
A PRINCE MYSELF.
HA! THE PRINCE OF WHAT?!
A LOT OF THINGS!
DO YOU MIND?
I'M TRYING TO HAVE
A CONVERSATION HERE.
MY APOLOGIES,
PRINCE SOKKA.
SO, IT LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA
BE IN TOWN FOR A WHILE.
I'M THINKING
MAYBE WE COULD...
DO AN ACTIVITY TOGETHER?
DO AN ACTIVITY?!
[COUGHS]
VERY SMOOTH.
MASTER PAKKU,
MEET YOUR
NEWEST STUDENT:
THE AVATAR.
JUST BECAUSE
YOU'RE DESTINED
TO SAVE THE WORLD,
DON'T EXPECT ANY
SPECIAL TREATMENT.
MY FRIEND
AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO START TRAINING
WITH YOU...
AFTER WE RELAX FOR
A COUPLE OF DAYS.
IF YOU WANT TO RELAX,
THEN I SUGGEST VISITING
A TROPICAL ISLAND.
IF NOT, I'LL SEE
YOU BOTH AT SUNRISE.
GOOD NIGHT.
FOR THE LAST TIME,
I'M NOT PLAYING
THE SUNGI HORN.
NO, IT'S ABOUT
OUR PLANS.
THERE IS A BIT
OF A PROBLEM.
I'M TAKING YOUR CREW.
WHAT?!
I'VE RECRUITED THEM
FOR A LITTLE EXPEDITION
TO THE NORTH POLE.
UNCLE, IS
THAT TRUE?
I'M AFRAID SO.
HE'S TAKING
EVERYONE--
EVEN THE COOK.
SORRY YOU
WON'T BE THERE
TO WATCH ME
CAPTURE THE AVATAR,
BUT I CAN'T HAVE YOU
GETTING IN MY WAY AGAIN.
[GROWLS]
NO!
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU WERE SKILLED
WITH BROADSWORDS,
PRINCE ZUKO.
I'M NOT.
THEY'RE
ANTIQUES.
JUST
DECORATIVE.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF
THE BLUE SPIRIT,
GENERAL IROH?
JUST RUMORS.
I DON'T THINK
HE IS REAL.
HE'S REAL,
ALL RIGHT.
HE'S A CRIMINAL
AND AN ENEMY OF
THE FIRE NATION.
BUT I HAVE
A FEELING JUSTICE
WILL CATCH UP
WITH HIM SOON.
GENERAL IROH, THE OFFER
TO JOIN MY MISSION
STILL STANDS...
IF YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
I'VE WAITED FOR THIS
DAY MY WHOLE LIFE.
I FINALLY GET
TO LEARN FROM
A REAL
WATERBENDING MASTER!
Aang: GOOD MORNING,
MASTER PAKKU!
NO, PLEASE!
MARCH RIGHT IN!
I'M NOT CONCENTRATING
OR ANYTHING.
UH, THIS IS
MY FRIEND--KATARA...
THE ONE
I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
I'M SORRY.
I THINK THERE'S BEEN
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
YOUR FRIEND WAS A GIRL.
IN OUR TRIBE,
IT IS FORBIDDEN
FOR WOMEN TO LEARN
WATERBENDING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU WON'T TEACH ME?!
I DIDN'T TRAVEL ACROSS
THE ENTIRE WORLD
SO YOU COULD TELL ME NO!
NO.
BUT THERE MUST BE OTHER
FEMALE WATERBENDERS
IN YOUR TRIBE.
HERE, THE WOMEN
LEARN FROM YAGODA
TO USE THEIR
WATERBENDING TO HEAL.
I'M SURE SHE WOULD
BE HAPPY TO TAKE YOU
AS HER STUDENT--
DESPITE YOUR
BAD ATTITUDE.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAL.
I WANT TO FIGHT!
I CAN SEE THAT.
BUT OUR TRIBE
HAS CUSTOMS, RULES.
WELL, YOUR
RULES STINK!
YEAH!
THEY'RE NOT FAIR.
IF YOU WON'T
TEACH KATARA, THEN--
THEN WHAT?!
THEN I WON'T
LEARN FROM YOU!
WELL, HAVE FUN
TEACHING YOURSELF.
I'M SURE YOU'LL
DO A GREAT JOB.
WAIT!
AANG DIDN'T
MEAN THAT.
YOU CAN'T RISK YOUR
TRAINING FOR ME.
YOU HAVE TO LEARN
FROM MASTER PAKKU,
EVEN IF HE IS
A BIG JERK.
WHY DON'T WE GET
STARTED, THEN.
Sokka: PRINCESS YUE,
GOOD MORNING!
[PANTING]
HEY, HOW ABOUT THAT
PICNIC LAST NIGHT?
BOY, YOUR DAD SURE KNOWS
HOW TO THROW A PARTY.
I'M HAPPY YOU
ENJOYED YOURSELF.
WELL, IT WASN'T
AS MUCH FUN
AFTER YOU LEFT.
SO, I'M STILL HOPING
WE CAN SEE MORE
OF EACH OTHER.
DO AN ACTIVITY,
YOU MEAN?
YES, AT A PLACE...
FOR SOME TIME.
I'D LOVE TO.
I'LL MEET YOU ON
THAT BRIDGE TONIGHT.
GREAT! I'LL SEE YOU--
AAGH!
[GIGGLES]
SORRY.
THAT'S OK.
IT WAS WORTH IT.
SEE YOU TONIGHT.
Zhao: I'M VERY
IMPRESSED.
YOU ALL SEEM
HIGHLY QUALIFIED
FOR THE MISSION
I HAVE IN MIND.
[SQUAWKING]
THAT'S SOME
TASTY GOLD.
WHAT DO YOU NEED US TO DO?
I BELIEVE YOU'RE
ACQUAINTED
WITH PRINCE ZUKO.
UM, HI.
ARE YOU YAGODA?
ARE YOU HERE FOR
THE HEALING LESSON?
I GUESS I AM.
WELCOME!
YOU'RE MOVING
THE WATER AROUND,
BUT YOU'RE NOT FEELING
THE PUSH AND PULL.
I'M TRYING.
[SLURP]
AHH!
MAYBE THAT MOVE IS
TOO ADVANCED FOR YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
AN EASIER ONE?
[GROWLS]
THANKS FOR THE LESSON.
SO, WHO'S
THE LUCKY BOY?
HUH?
YOUR BETROTHAL
NECKLACE.
YOU'RE GETTING
MARRIED, RIGHT?
OH, NO.
I DON'T THINK
I'M READY FOR THAT YET.
MY GRANDMOTHER GAVE
MY MOTHER THIS NECKLACE,
AND MY MOTHER
PASSED IT DOWN TO ME.
I RECOGNIZE
THIS CARVING!
I DON'T KNOW WHY I
DIDN'T REALIZE SOONER.
YOU'RE THE SPITTING
IMAGE OF KANNA.
WAIT!
HOW DO YOU KNOW
MY GRAN-GRAN'S NAME?
WHEN I WAS
ABOUT YOUR AGE,
I WAS FRIENDS
WITH KANNA.
SHE WAS BORN HERE--
IN THE NORTHERN
TRIBE.
SHE NEVER TOLD ME.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER HAD
AN ARRANGED MARRIAGE
WITH A YOUNG
WATERBENDER.
HE CARVED THAT
NECKLACE FOR HER.
IF GRAN-GRAN WAS ENGAGED,
WHY DID SHE LEAVE?
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S ALWAYS BEEN
A MYSTERY TO ME.
SHE LEFT WITHOUT
SAYING GOOD-BYE.
Iroh: GOOD LUCK!
THE CREW WANTED ME TO
WISH YOU SAFE TRAVELS.
GOOD RIDDANCE TO
THOSE TRAITORS.
IT'S A LOVELY NIGHT
FOR A WALK.
WHY DON'T YOU
JOIN ME?
IT WOULD CLEAR
YOUR HEAD.
OR JUST STAY
IN YOUR ROOM
AND SIT IN THE DARK.
WHATEVER MAKES
YOU HAPPY.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[HUMMING]
WHOA!
CAREFUL WITH
THE BLASTING JELLY.
[SQUEAK]
OOH!
UNCLE?
UNCLE, IS THAT YOU?
[SQUAWK]
AAH!
[ZUKO SCREAMING]
ZUKO!
ZUKO.
HI, PRINCESS YUE.
I MADE YOU
SOMETHING.
I CARVED IT MYSELF.
IT'S A BEAR.
ACTUALLY, IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE A FISH.
SEE, IT HAS A FIN.
OH.
I'M SORRY.
I MADE A MISTAKE.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE ASKED
YOU TO COME HERE.
[GRUNTS]
Katara: HOW'S WARRIOR
TRAINING GOING?
[GROWLS]
THAT BAD?
NO, IT'S PRINCESS YUE.
I DON'T GET IT.
ONE MINUTE, SHE WANTS
TO GO OUT WITH ME,
AND THE NEXT, SHE'S
TELLING ME TO GET LOST.
SO, HOW'S
WATERBENDING TRAINING?
MASTER POOP-HEAD
WON'T TEACH HER
BECAUSE SHE'S
A GIRL.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
TEACH HER, AANG?
WHY DIDN'T
I THINK OF THAT?!
AT NIGHT,
YOU CAN TEACH ME
WHATEVER MOVES YOU LEARN
FROM MASTER PAKKU.
THAT WAY, YOU HAVE
SOMEONE TO PRACTICE WITH,
AND I GET TO LEARN
WATERBENDING.
EVERYONE'S HAPPY!
I'M NOT HAPPY.
BUT YOU'RE NEVER HAPPY.
COME ON, AANG.
MASTER PAKKU
SAID THIS MOVE
IS ALL ABOUT SINKING
AND FLOATING.
I GOT IT!
THAT WAS AMAZING!
THAT WASN'T ME.
I WAS JUST SHOWING
KATARA A FEW MOVES.
YOU HAVE
DISRESPECTED ME,
MY TEACHINGS, AND MY
ENTIRE CULTURE.
I'M SORRY, I--
YOU ARE NO LONGER
WELCOME AS MY STUDENT.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT ME TO DO?
FORCE MASTER PAKKU
TO TAKE AANG BACK
AS HIS STUDENT?
YES. PLEASE.
I SUSPECT HE MIGHT
CHANGE HIS MIND
IF YOU SWALLOW YOUR PRIDE
AND APOLOGIZE TO HIM.
FINE.
I'M WAITING,
LITTLE GIRL.
NO!
NO WAY AM I APOLOGIZING
TO A SOUR OLD MAN
LIKE YOU!
Aang: UH, KATARA...
I'LL BE OUTSIDE
IF YOU'RE MAN ENOUGH
TO FIGHT ME.
I'M SURE SHE
DIDN'T MEAN THAT.
YEAH, I THINK
SHE DID.
I'M DEVASTATED TO HEAR
ABOUT PRINCE ZUKO.
JUST DEVASTATED.
THE FIRE LORD
WILL NOT BE PLEASED
WHEN HE LEARNS WHO
WAS RESPONSIBLE.
YOU KNOW WHO WAS
BEHIND THE ATTACK?
YES. PIRATES.
WE HAD A RUN-IN WITH
THEM A WHILE BACK.
THEY WANTED REVENGE.
SO, HAVE YOU
RECONSIDERED MY OFFER?
YES, I ACCEPT.
IT WILL BE AN HONOR
TO SERVE AS YOUR GENERAL.
TO THE FIRE NATION.
TO VICTORY!
Sokka: ARE YOU
CRAZY, KATARA?
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
WIN THIS FIGHT.
I KNOW. I DON'T CARE.
YOU DON'T
HAVE TO DO
THIS FOR ME.
I CAN FIND
ANOTHER TEACHER.
- I'M NOT DOING
IT FOR YOU.
SOMEONE NEEDS TO SLAP
SOME SENSE INTO THAT GUY.
SO, YOU DECIDED TO SHOW UP?
AREN'T YOU
GONNA FIGHT?
GO BACK TO
THE HEALING HUTS WITH THE OTHER
WOMEN, WHERE YOU BELONG.
FINE.
YOU WANT TO LEARN
TO FIGHT SO BAD,
STUDY CLOSELY.
DON'T WORRY. I'M NOT
GOING TO HURT YOU.
OW!
YOU CAN'T KNOCK ME DOWN!
Aang:
GO, KATARA!
[CHEERING]
[PANTING]
WELL, I'M IMPRESSED.
YOU ARE AN EXCELLENT
WATERBENDER.
BUT YOU STILL WON'T
TEACH ME, WILL YOU?
NO.
[PANTING]
THIS FIGHT IS OVER.
COME BACK HERE.
I'M NOT FINISHED YET.
YES. YOU ARE.
THIS IS MY
NECKLACE.
NO, IT'S NOT. IT'S MINE.
GIVE IT BACK!
I MADE THIS
60 YEARS AGO...
FOR THE LOVE
OF MY LIFE--
FOR KANNA.
MY GRAN-GRAN WAS
SUPPOSED TO MARRY YOU?
OUR PLAN IS
WORKING PERFECTLY.
ZHAO DOESN'T
SUSPECT A THING.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE
TO DO THIS.
NO NEPHEW OF MINE
IS GOING TO
STOW AWAY ON A SHIP
WITHOUT SOME BACKUP.
THANK YOU, UNCLE.
[DOOR OPENS]
SOMEONE'S COMING.
STAY HIDDEN UNTIL WE
GET TO THE NORTH POLE
AND THE AVATAR
WILL BE YOURS.
GOOD LUCK.
I CARVED
THIS NECKLACE FOR
YOUR GRANDMOTHER
WHEN WE GOT ENGAGED.
I THOUGHT WE
WOULD HAVE A LONG
HAPPY LIFE TOGETHER.
I LOVED HER.
BUT SHE DIDN'T
LOVE YOU, DID SHE?
IT WAS AN ARRANGED
MARRIAGE.
GRAN-GRAN WOULDN'T
LET YOUR TRIBE'S
STUPID CUSTOMS RUN HER LIFE.
THAT'S WHY SHE LEFT.
IT MUST HAVE TAKEN
A LOT OF COURAGE.
[SOBBING]
GO GET HER.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT FROM ME?
NOTHING.
I JUST WANT
YOU TO KNOW
I THINK YOU'RE
BEAUTIFUL.
AND I NEVER
THOUGHT A GIRL
LIKE YOU
WOULD EVEN NOTICE
A GUY LIKE ME.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NO, NO.
SEE, THAT'S
THE THING.
I THINK I DO
UNDERSTAND NOW.
YOU'RE A PRINCESS,
AND I'M...
I'M JUST
A SOUTHERN PEASANT.
NO, SOKKA.
IT'S OK.
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO SAY ANYTHING.
I'LL SEE YOU
AROUND, OK.
OK, NOW I'M
REALLY CONFUSED!
HAPPY,
BUT CONFUSED.
I DO LIKE YOU--A LOT!
BUT WE CAN'T BE TOGETHER.
AND NOT FOR
THE REASON YOU THINK.
IT'S BECAUSE...
I'M ENGAGED.
I'M SORRY.
NOT BAD.
HA HA HA HA.
KEEP PRACTICING,
AND MAYBE YOU'LL GET IT
BY THE TIME
YOU'RE MY AGE.
[PANTING]
HEY, KATARA.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
IT'S PAST SUNRISE.
YOU'RE LATE.
GOOD TO SEE
YOU HERE.
YOU, TOO.
MY FLEET IS READY.
SET A COURSE FOR
THE NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
♪