Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
Girl: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
THERE IT IS.
THE NORTHERN
WATER TRIBE.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE DESTINED
TO SAVE THE WORLD
DON'T EXPECT
ANY SPECIAL TREATMENT.
MY FRIENDS AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO START TRAINING WITH YOU.
I DO LIKE YOU...
A LOT,
BUT WE CAN'T
BE TOGETHER.
I'M ENGAGED.
STAY HIDDEN UNTIL WE
GET TO THE NORTH POLE
AND AVATAR WILL BE YOURS.
MY FLEET IS READY.
SET A COURSE FOR THE
NORTHERN WATER TRIBE.
WHOA!
NICE TRY,
PUPIL SANGOK.
A COUPLE OF MORE YEARS,
AND YOU MIGHT BE READY
TO FIGHT A SEA SPONGE.
WHOA!
WOULD ANYONE CARE FOR
A REMATCH WITH KATARA?
[GROANING]
KATARA, YOU'VE
ADVANCED MORE QUICKLY
THAN ANY STUDENT
I'VE EVER TRAINED.
YOU HAVE PROVEN THAT WITH
FIERCE DETERMINATION,
PASSION, AND HARD WORK,
YOU CAN ACCOMPLISH ANYTHING.
RAW TALENT ALONE
IS NOT ENOUGH...
PUPIL AANG!
YES, MASTER PAKKU?
CARE TO STEP INTO
THE SPARRING CIRCLE?
I FIGURE
SINCE YOU'VE FOUND TIME
TO PLAY WITH HOUSE PETS,
YOU MUST HAVE ALREADY
MASTERED WATERBENDING.
I WOULDN'T
SAY MASTERED,
BUT CHECK THIS OUT!
Girl: SO, THEY
DON'T HAVE PALACES
IN THE SOUTHERN TRIBE?
ARE YOU KIDDING?
I GREW UP IN
A BLOCK OF ICE--
IT'S NOT EXACTLY
A CULTURAL HUB.
[GIGGLES]
SOKKA, THIS IS WRONG.
WHAT'S WRONG?
WE'RE TAKING A WALK!
I'M ENGAGED.
IT JUST FEELS...
I KNOW WHAT YOU NEED--
YOU NEED TO MEET
MY GOOD FRIEND APPA.
WHO?
[GROWLING]
APPA AND I
GO WAY BACK,
DON'T WE, BOY?
AAGH!
EASY!
DOWN, BOY!
NO, UP!
Yue: LOOKS LIKE
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
GIVING APPA
ENOUGH ATTENTION.
[CHUCKLES]
SO, HOW DOES
THIS WORK?
YOU HANGING ON TIGHT?
MM-HMM.
YIP, YIP.
OH, MY GOODNESS!
WOW!
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU
DO THIS EVERY DAY.
YEAH, WE PRETTY
MUCH LIVE UP HERE.
IS IT ALWAYS THIS
COLD IN THE SKY?
NOT WHEN YOU'RE
WITH SOMEONE.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL UP HERE.
YEAH.
WHOO, YEAH!
[INHALES DEEPLY]
GOOD TIMES,
GOOD TIMES.
HEY, LOOK.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
[GROWLS]
OH, NO.
[LAUGHING]
[COUGHS]
Sokka: SOOT.
Yue: WHAT?
I'VE SEEN
IT BEFORE...
RIGHT BEFORE MY VILLAGE
WAS ATTACKED.
IT'S SOOT MIXED
WITH SNOW.
BUT WHY?
IT'S THE FIRE NATION.
THEY'VE CLOSED IN
ON THE NORTH POLE.
AND FROM THE LOOKS
OF THIS STUFF,
I'D SAY THERE'S
A LOT OF THEM.
Man: THIS WILL TRULY BE
ONE FOR THE HISTORY
BOOKS, GENERAL IROH.
JUST THINK:
CENTURIES FROM NOW,
PEOPLE WILL STUDY
THE GREAT ADMIRAL ZHAO,
WHO DESTROYED THE LAST
OF THE WATER TRIBE
CIVILIZATION.
YOU'RE LUCKY YOU'RE
HERE TO SEE IT.
BE CAREFUL WHAT
YOU WISH FOR, ADMIRAL.
HISTORY IS NOT ALWAYS
KIND TO ITS SUBJECTS.
I SUPPOSE YOU SPEAK
FROM EXPERIENCE.
BUT, REST ASSURED,
THIS WILL BE
NOTHING LIKE
YOUR LEGENDARY FAILURE
AT BA SENG SE.
I HOPE NOT,
FOR YOUR SAKE.
TELL THE CAPTAINS
TO PREPARE
FOR FIRST STRIKE.
WE'LL BE LANDING SOON.
DO YOU HAVE A PLAN?
I'M WORKING ON IT,
UNCLE.
[DRUM POUNDING]
WHAT'S WRONG?
WE HAVE TO GO!
NO, SOKKA...
WAIT.
I CAN'T SEE
YOU ANYMORE--
NOT AT ALL.
WHAT? WE'RE JUST FRIENDS.
I WISH WE COULD
JUST BE FRIENDS...
BUT I LIKE YOU
TOO MUCH,
AND IT'S TOO CONFUSING
TO BE AROUND YOU.
I'M MARRYING
SOMEONE ELSE.
YOU DON'T LOVE HIM,
DO YOU?
YOU DON'T EVEN
SEEM TO LIKE HIM.
BUT I DO LOVE
MY PEOPLE.
YOU'RE NOT
MARRYING THEM!
YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE DUTIES
TO MY FATHER,
TO MY TRIBE.
I HAVE TO DO THIS.
GOOD-BYE.
THE DAY WE HAVE FEARED
FOR SO LONG HAS ARRIVED--
THE FIRE NATION
IS ON OUR DOORSTEP.
IT IS WITH GREAT SADNESS
I CALL MY FAMILY
HERE BEFORE ME,
KNOWING WELL THAT
SOME OF THESE FACES
ARE ABOUT TO VANISH
FROM OUR TRIBE...
THEY WILL NEVER
VANISH FROM OUR HEARTS.
NOW, AS WE APPROACH
THE BATTLE FOR OUR EXISTENCE,
I CALL UPON THE GREAT SPIRITS...
SPIRIT OF THE OCEAN,
SPIRIT OF THE MOON,
BE WITH US!
I'M GOING TO
NEED VOLUNTEERS
FOR A DANGEROUS MISSION...
COUNT ME IN.
SOKKA...
BE WARNED:
MANY OF YOU WILL
NOT RETURN.
COME FORWARD TO
RECEIVE MY MARK
IF YOU ACCEPT THE TASK.
THE STILLNESS BEFORE
BATTLE IS UNBEARABLE.
SUCH A QUIET DREAD.
I WASN'T THERE WHEN
THE FIRE NATION
ATTACKED MY PEOPLE.
I'M GONNA MAKE
A DIFFERENCE THIS TIME.
[SCREAMING]
[SNARLS]
YIP, YIP!
KATARA!
[YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
I'LL TAKE IT
FROM HERE, BOY.
APPA!
THANKS FOR
THE RESCUE, BUDDY.
YOU'VE GOTTA
BE KIDDING ME.
MEN, YOU'LL BE INFILTRATING
THE FIRE NATION NAVY.
THAT MEANS YOU'LL ALL NEED
ONE OF THESE UNIFORMS...
[LAUGHTER]
WHAT'S YOUR
PROBLEM?
FIRE NAVY UNIFORMS
DON'T LOOK LIKE THAT.
OF COURSE
THEY DO.
THESE ARE
REAL UNIFORMS
CAPTURED FROM ACTUAL
FIRE NAVY SOLDIERS.
WHEN, LIKE,
100 YEARS AGO?
85.
THE FIRE NATION
DOESN'T WEAR SHOULDER
SPIKES ANYMORE.
THE NEWER
UNIFORMS ARE
MORE STREAMLINED.
HOW DO WE KNOW WE
CAN TRUST THIS GUY?
SUCH BOLD TALK
FOR A NEW RECRUIT.
SOKKA IS FROM OUR
SISTER TRIBE, HAHN.
HE IS A CAPABLE WARRIOR,
AND I VALUE HIS INPUT.
NOW, OUR FIRST
OBJECTIVE IS
TO DETERMINE
THE IDENTITY OF
THEIR COMMANDING
OFFICER.
HIS NAME IS ZHAO.
MIDDLE-AGED,
BIG SIDEBURNS,
BIGGER TEMPER...
SOKKA, I WANT
YOU TO TELL
EVERYTHING YOU
KNOW TO HAHN--
HE'S LEADING
THIS MISSION.
HAHN, SHOW SOKKA
YOUR RESPECT.
I EXPECT NOTHING LESS
FROM MY FUTURE SON-IN-LAW.
PRINCESS YUE'S
MARRYING YOU?
YEAH. WHAT OF IT?
NOTHING.
CONGRATULATIONS.
STOP THOSE FIREBALLS!
IT'S ALMOST
TWILIGHT, ADMIRAL.
AS YOUR MILITARY
CONSULTANT,
I MUST ADVISE YOU
TO HALT YOUR ATTACK.
THE WATERBENDERS
DRAW THEIR POWER
FROM THE MOON,
AND IT IS NEARLY
FULL TONIGHT.
YOU SHOULD WAIT
AND RESUME
THE ATTACK
AT DAYBREAK.
OH, I AM WELL AWARE
OF THE MOON PROBLEM.
AND I'M WORKING
ON A SOLUTION.
BUT FOR NOW, DAYBREAK IT IS.
Yue: THEY'VE
STOPPED FIRING.
AANG!
I CAN'T DO IT.
I CAN'T DO IT...
Katara: WHAT HAPPENED?!
I MUST HAVE TAKEN OUT
A DOZEN FIRE NAVY SHIPS,
BUT THERE'S JUST
TOO MANY OF THEM.
I CAN'T FIGHT THEM ALL!
BUT YOU HAVE TO.
YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
I'M JUST ONE KID.
IF YOU ARE FISHING FOR
AN OCTOPUS, MY NEPHEW,
YOU NEED A TIGHTLY
WOVEN NET,
OR HE WILL
SQUEEZE THROUGH
THE TINIEST HOLE
AND ESCAPE.
I DON'T NEED YOUR
WISDOM RIGHT NOW, UNCLE.
I'M SORRY, I JUST
NAG YOU BECAUSE...
WELL, EVER SINCE
I LOST MY SON...
UNCLE, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO SAY IT.
I THINK OF YOU
AS MY OWN.
I KNOW, UNCLE.
WE'LL MEET AGAIN...
AFTER I HAVE THE AVATAR.
REMEMBER YOUR
BREATH OF FIRE--
IT COULD SAVE YOUR
LIFE OUT THERE.
I WILL.
AND PUT YOUR
HOOD UP--
KEEP YOUR
EARS WARM.
I'LL BE FINE!
LET ME TELL YOU, SOKKA,
I'VE COURTED
A LOT OF GIRLS,
BUT YUE IS THE FINEST...
AND SHE COMES WITH
THE MOST PERKS.
PERKS?!
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
I MEAN--
YUE'S NICE AND EVERYTHING,
BUT THE POINTS I'LL
GAIN WITH THE CHIEF
AREN'T BAD EITHER.
PRINCESS YUE IS WASTED
ON A SELF-ABSORBED
WEASEL LIKE YOU!
WHOA, HANG ON!
WHAT DO YOU CARE?
YOU'RE JUST A SIMPLE RUBE
FROM THE SOUTHERN TRIBE.
WHAT WOULD YOU KNOW
OF THE POLITICAL
COMPLEXITIES OF OUR LIFE?
NO OFFENSE.
[SCREAMS]
YOU'RE JUST A JERK
WITHOUT A SOUL!
NO OFFENSE!
THAT'S ENOUGH!
SOKKA, YOU'RE OFF
THE MISSION.
ALL RIGHT,
FALL IN, MEN!
EVERYBODY LISTEN
TO WHAT I SAY,
AND WE'LL TAKE
OUT THIS ADMIRAL CHO
IN NO TIME!
IT'S ADMIRAL ZHAO!
[ANIMALS CALLING]
WHERE ARE THEY GOING?
THEY'RE COMING UP
FOR AIR SOMEWHERE.
[INHALES DEEPLY]
Yue: THE LEGENDS
SAY THE MOON
WAS THE FIRST
WATERBENDER.
OUR ANCESTORS
SAW HOW IT PUSHED
AND PULLED THE TIDES,
AND LEARNED HOW TO
DO IT THEMSELVES.
Katara: I'VE ALWAYS NOTICED
MY WATERBENDING
IS STRONGER AT NIGHT.
OUR STRENGTH COMES FROM
THE SPIRIT OF THE MOON,
OUR LIFE COMES
FROM THE SPIRIT
OF THE OCEAN.
THEY WORK TOGETHER
TO KEEP BALANCE.
THE SPIRITS--
MAYBE I CAN FIND THEM
AND GET THEIR HELP.
HOW CAN YOU DO THAT?
THE AVATAR IS THE BRIDGE
BETWEEN OUR WORLD
AND THE SPIRIT WORLD.
AANG CAN TALK TO THEM!
MAYBE THEY'LL
GIVE YOU THE WISDOM
TO WIN THIS BATTLE.
OR MAYBE THEY'LL
UNLEASH
A CRAZY-AMAZING
SPIRIT ATTACK ON
THE FIRE NATION!
OR WISDOM,
THAT'S GOOD, TOO.
THE ONLY PROBLEM IS,
THE LAST TIME YOU
GOT TO THE SPIRIT
WORLD BY ACCIDENT.
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO
GET THERE THIS TIME?
I HAVE AN IDEA.
FOLLOW ME.
SO, IS THIS THE WAY
TO THE SPIRIT WORLD?
HA HA HA. NO.
YOU'LL HAVE TO GET
THERE ON YOUR OWN.
BUT I CAN TAKE YOU
TO THE MOST SPIRITUAL PLACE
IN THE ENTIRE NORTH POLE.
[GASPS]
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D
MISS GRASS THIS MUCH!
IT'S SO WARM HERE!
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
IT'S THE CENTER
OF ALL SPIRITUAL
ENERGY IN OUR LAND.
YOU'RE RIGHT, YUE.
I CAN FEEL...
SOMETHING.
IT'S SO...
TRANQUIL.
[ANIMALS CALLING]
[SHUDDERING]
BE QUIET!
[LOWING STOPS]
[LOWING]
Chief: IS SOMETHING
WRONG, SOKKA?
OH, NO.
HAHN'S OUT THERE ON
THE TOP-SECRET MISSION,
WHILE I'M HERE
SHARPENING MY BOOMERANG.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
LISTEN TO ME.
I TOOK YOU OFF THE MISSION
FOR SELFISH REASONS--
I HAVE A SPECIAL TASK
IN MIND FOR YOU.
WHAT, YOU WANT ME TO
SCRUB THE BARRACKS?
I WANT YOU
TO GUARD MY DAUGHTER--
PRINCESS YUE.
OH. SURE.
THAT SHOULDN'T
BE TOO HARD.
[GASPING]
Yue, whispering:
Why is he sitting
like that?
He's meditating--
trying to cross over
into the spirit world.
It takes all
his concentration.
Is there any way
we can help?
Aang: HOW ABOUT
SOME QUIET?!
COME ON, GUYS,
I CAN HEAR EVERY
WORD YOU'RE SAYING.
IS HE OK?
HE'S CROSSING INTO
THE SPIRIT WORLD.
HE'LL BE FINE AS LONG AS
WE DON'T MOVE HIS BODY.
THAT'S HIS WAY BACK TO
THE PHYSICAL WORLD.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
GET SOME HELP?
NO. HE'S MY FRIEND.
I'M PERFECTLY CAPABLE
OF PROTECTING HIM.
Zuko: WELL, AREN'T YOU
A BIG GIRL NOW?
NO...
YES.
HAND HIM OVER AND I
WON'T HAVE TO HURT YOU.
HYAH!
I SEE YOU'VE LEARNED
A NEW TRICK.
BUT I DIDN'T COME
THIS FAR TO LOSE TO YOU.
YOU LITTLE PEASANT.
YOU'VE FOUND A MASTER,
HAVEN'T YOU?
HYAH!
HYAH! HYAH...
AAH! UH!
IT'S DAYBREAK AT LAST.
LET'S WRITE HISTORY.
YOU RISE WITH THE MOON,
I RISE WITH THE SUN.
[ALL YELLING]
THE WATER TRIBE CAN TRY
TO RESIST THE INEVITABLE,
BUT THEIR CITY
WILL FALL TODAY.
[GASPS]
AANG?!
WHAT HAPPENED?!
WHERE'S ZUKO?!
HE TOOK AANG...
HE TOOK HIM RIGHT
OUT FROM UNDER ME.
Sokka: WHERE
DID THEY GO?
♪