Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
Katara: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Katara: THE NORTHERN
WATER TRIBE.
WE'RE FINALLY HERE.
Zhao: THERE'S A REASON THEY'VE
SURVIVED 100 YEARS OF WAR.
WE'LL NEED A MASSIVE
INVASION FORCE.
THE SPIRITS!
MAYBE I CAN FIND THEM
AND GET THEIR HELP!
Uncle: THE WATERBENDERS
DRAW THEIR POWER
FROM THE MOON.
Zhao: OH, I'M WELL AWARE
OF THE MOON PROBLEM,
AND I AM WORKING
ON A SOLUTION.
Uncle: ZHAO DOESN'T
SUSPECT A THING.
STAY HIDDEN UNTIL WE GET
TO THE NORTH POLE,
AND THE AVATAR WILL BE YOURS.
HE'S CROSSING
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
HE'LL BE FINE
AS LONG AS WE DON'T
MOVE HIS BODY.
UNH!
Katara: I CAN'T
BELIEVE I LOST HIM.
Sokka: YOU DID
EVERYTHING YOU COULD.
AND NOW WE NEED TO
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO GET HIM BACK.
ZUKO CAN'T HAVE
GOTTEN FAR.
WE'LL FIND HIM.
AANG'S GONNA BE FINE.
OK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU STAY HERE, MOMO--
IN CASE AANG
COMES BACK.
YIP, YIP!
Man: OM.
OM.
HELLO?
I'M SORRY
TO DISTURB YOU.
I JUST REALLY
NEED TO FIND
THE MOON
AND THE OCEAN SPIRITS.
GO AWAY.
YOU'RE STILL HERE?
YES, I NEED--
OM!
PERHAPS THAT THING
WILL HELP YOU.
CHASE IT!
[SIGHS]
FINALLY.
[SCREAMS]
COME BACK!
HELLO, AANG.
ROKU?!
HUH?!
[GASPING]
SHELTER!
ROKU, THE WATER TRIBE
IS UNDER ATTACK!
I NEED TO FIND THE OCEAN
AND THE MOON SPIRITS.
THE OCEAN AND THE MOON
ARE ANCIENT SPIRITS--
THEY CROSSED OVER
FROM THE SPIRIT WORLD
TO THE MORTAL WORLD
VERY NEAR THE BEGINNING.
THERE IS ONLY ONE
SPIRIT I KNOW OF
WHO IS OLD ENOUGH
TO REMEMBER...
WHO?
THE SPIRIT'S
NAME IS KOH,
BUT HE IS VERY
DANGEROUS--
THEY CALL HIM
"THE FACE STEALER."
WHEN YOU SPEAK WITH HIM,
YOU MUST BE
VERY CAREFUL
TO SHOW NO
EMOTION AT ALL--
NOT THE SLIGHTEST
EXPRESSION--
OR HE WILL STEAL
YOUR FACE.
I FINALLY HAVE YOU,
BUT I CAN'T GET YOU HOME
BECAUSE OF THIS BLIZZARD.
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING.
NOT THAT YOU WOULD
UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE LIKE MY SISTER.
EVERYTHING ALWAYS
CAME EASY TO HER.
SHE'S A FIREBENDING
PRODIGY...
AND EVERYONE ADORES HER.
MY FATHER SAYS SHE
WAS BORN LUCKY.
HE SAYS I WAS LUCKY
TO BE BORN.
I DON'T NEED
LUCK, THOUGH--
I DON'T WANT IT.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD TO
STRUGGLE AND FIGHT,
AND THAT'S MADE
ME STRONG...
IT'S MADE ME WHO I AM.
Uncle: I DON'T NEED
TO REMIND YOU
WE HAVE
A TIME LIMIT.
IF WE DON'T DEFEAT
THE WATER TRIBE
BEFORE THE FULL
MOON RISES,
THEY WILL BE
UNDEFEATABLE.
I ASSURE YOU--
I HAVE EVERYTHING
UNDER CONTROL.
I INTEND TO REMOVE
THE MOON AS A FACTOR.
REMOVE THE MOON?
HOW?
- ADMIRAL CHOI!
PREPARE TO MEET
YOUR FATE!
WHOA!
[SPLASH]
AS I WAS SAYING.
YEARS AGO,
I STUMBLED UPON
A GREAT AND POWERFUL SECRET--
THE IDENTITY OF THE MOON
SPIRIT'S MORTAL FORM.
WHAT?!
I WAS A YOUNG LIEUTENANT
SERVING UNDER GENERAL XU
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM.
I DISCOVERED
A HIDDEN LIBRARY--
UNDERGROUND, IN FACT.
I TORE THROUGH
SCROLL AFTER SCROLL.
ONE OF THEM CONTAINED
A DETAILED ILLUSTRATION--
AND THE WORDS "MOON"
AND "OCEAN."
I KNEW THEN THAT THESE
SPIRITS COULD BE FOUND...
AND KILLED...
AND THAT IT WAS MY
DESTINY TO DO SO.
ZHAO, THE SPIRITS
ARE NOT TO BE
TRIFLED WITH!
YES, YES, I KNOW YOU
FEAR THE SPIRITS, IROH--
I HAVE HEARD RUMOURS
ABOUT YOUR JOURNEY
INTO THE SPIRIT WORLD.
BUT THE OCEAN AND MOON
GAVE UP THEIR IMMORTALITY
TO BECOME A PART
OF OUR WORLD.
AND NOW THEY WILL
FACE THE CONSEQUENCES.
[CHATTERING]
[GASPS]
PHEW!
YOU'RE JUST
A CURLY-TAILED BLUENOSE.
[GASPS]
SHOW NO FEAR.
SHOW NO EMOTION AT ALL.
HELLO?
I'M LOOKING FOR
A SPIRIT NAMED KOH.
WELCOME.
THANK YOU.
MY OLD FRIEND,
THE AVATAR--
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME.
YOU KNOW ME?
HOW COULD I FORGET YOU?
ONE OF YOUR PREVIOUS
INCARNATIONS
TRIED TO SLAY ME--
MAYBE 800 OR 900
YEARS AGO.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
WHY DID HE--OR I--
TRY TO KILL YOU?
OH, IT WAS
SOMETHING ABOUT
STEALING THE FACE
OF SOMEONE YOU LOVED.
[LAUGHING]
OF COURSE, THAT'S
ALL BEHIND US.
WHY SHOULD I HOLD
A GRUDGE AGAINST YOU
FOR SOMETHING
IN A PAST LIFE?
AFTER ALL--
YOU'RE A DIFFERENT
PERSON NOW.
YOU'VE COME TO ME
WITH A NEW FACE.
GUESS WE'LL BE
HERE AWHILE.
Yue: DON'T WORRY.
PRINCE ZUKO CAN'T
BE GETTING TOO FAR
IN THIS WEATHER.
I'M NOT WORRIED
THEY'LL GET AWAY
IN THE BLIZZARD.
I'M WORRIED
THAT THEY WON'T.
Sokka: THEY'RE NOT GONNA
DIE IN THIS BLIZZARD.
IF WE KNOW ANYTHING,
IT'S THAT ZUKO
NEVER GIVES UP.
THEY'LL SURVIVE--
AND WE'LL FIND THEM.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE I'VE ADDED A CHILD'S
FACE TO MY COLLECTION.
SO...
HOW MAY I HELP YOU?
Aang: I NEED TO FIND
THE MOON AND THE OCEAN.
THEIR SPIRIT NAMES
ARE "TUI" AND "LA--"
PUSH AND PULL.
AND THAT HAS
BEEN THE NATURE
OF THEIR RELATIONSHIP
FOR ALL TIME.
PLEASE, HELP ME
FIND THEM.
AN ENTIRE CULTURE
COULD BE DESTROYED
IF I DON'T
GET THEIR HELP.
OH, YOU THINK YOU
NEED THEIR HELP?
ACTUALLY, IT'S QUITE
THE OTHER WAY AROUND.
SOMEONE IS GOING
TO KILL THEM!
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
HOW CAN I FIND THEM
AND PROTECT THEM?
YOU'VE ALREADY MET
THEM, ACTUALLY.
TUI AND LA--
YOUR MOON AND OCEAN--
HAVE ALWAYS CIRCLED EACH
OTHER IN AN ETERNAL DANCE.
THEY BALANCE EACH OTHER:
PUSH AND PULL,
LIFE AND DEATH,
GOOD AND EVIL...
YIN AND YANG.
THE KOI FISH!
I MUST BE GOING NOW.
WE'LL MEET AGAIN.
THE SPIRITS
ARE IN TROUBLE!
I NEED TO GET BACK
TO THE PHYSICAL WORLD!
A FRIEND IS HERE
TO GUIDE YOU BACK.
HEI BAI!
[MEWS]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
WE'LL BE
FOLLOWING THIS MAP
TO A VERY
SPECIAL LOCATION.
AND WHEN
WE GET THERE...
WE'RE GOING FISHING.
THIS IS WHERE
I CAME IN...
BUT HOW DO I GET BACK?
GOOD RIDDANCE.
[SCREAMS]
MOMO!
MOMO?
OH, NO...
WHERE'S MY BODY?
LOOK!
THAT'S GOT TO
BE AANG!
YIP, YIP!
HUH?!
[STRAINING]
WELCOME BACK.
GOOD TO BE BACK.
[GRUNTING]
THAT WON'T BE
ENOUGH TO ESCAPE.
APPA!
WHOA!
HERE FOR A REMATCH?
TRUST ME, ZUKO,
IT'S NOT GOING TO
BE MUCH OF A MATCH.
HEY, THIS IS
SOME QUALITY ROPE.
WE NEED TO GET
TO THE OASIS!
THE SPIRITS
ARE IN TROUBLE.
WAIT--WE CAN'T JUST
LEAVE HIM HERE.
SURE, WE CAN.
LET'S GO.
NO.
IF WE LEAVE HIM,
HE'LL DIE.
[GRUNTS]
Sokka: YEAH, THIS MAKES
A LOT OF SENSE--
LET'S BRING THE GUY
WHO'S CONSTANTLY
TRYING TO KILL US.
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
ARE YOU OK?
I FEEL FAINT.
I FEEL IT, TOO.
THE MOON SPIRIT
IS IN TROUBLE.
I OWE THE MOON
SPIRIT MY LIFE.
WHAT DO
YOU MEAN?
WHEN I WAS BORN,
I WAS VERY SICK
AND VERY WEAK.
MOST BABIES CRY
WHEN THEY'RE BORN,
BUT I WAS BORN AS
IF I WERE ASLEEP,
MY EYES CLOSED.
OUR HEALERS DID
EVERYTHING THEY COULD.
THEY TOLD MY
MOTHER AND FATHER
I WAS GOING TO DIE.
MY FATHER PLEADED WITH
THE SPIRITS TO SAVE ME.
THAT NIGHT--BENEATH
THE FULL MOON--
HE BROUGHT ME TO THE OASIS
AND PLACED ME IN THE POND.
MY DARK HAIR TURNED WHITE.
I OPENED MY EYES
AND BEGAN TO CRY...
WAAH!
AND THEY KNEW I WOULD LIVE.
THAT'S WHY MY MOTHER
NAMED ME YUE,
FOR THE MOON.
Zhao: I AM A LEGEND NOW.
THE FIRE NATION
WILL FOR GENERATIONS
TELL STORIES ABOUT
THE GREAT ZHAO,
WHO DARKENED THE MOON.
THEY WILL CALL ME
ZHAO THE CONQUEROR...
ZHAO THE MOON-SLAYER...
ZHAO THE INVINCIBLE!
[CHITTERING]
GET IT OFF!
DON'T BOTHER.
ZHAO, DON'T!
IT'S MY DESTINY...
TO DESTROY THE MOON
AND THE WATER TRIBE.
DESTROYING THE MOON
WON'T JUST HURT
THE WATER TRIBE,
IT WILL HURT EVERYONE--
INCLUDING YOU.
WITHOUT THE MOON,
EVERYTHING WOULD
FALL OUT OF BALANCE--
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT KIND OF CHAOS
THAT WOULD UNLEASH
ON THE WORLD.
Uncle: HE'S RIGHT, ZHAO.
GENERAL IROH,
WHY AM I NOT
SURPRISED
TO DISCOVER
YOUR TREACHERY.
I'M NO TRAITOR, ZHAO.
THE FIRE NATION
NEEDS THE MOON, TOO.
WE ALL DEPEND
ON THE BALANCE.
WHATEVER YOU DO
TO THAT SPIRIT,
I'LL UNLEASH ON
YOU TENFOLD!
LET IT GO NOW!
[YELLING]
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
THERE'S NO HOPE NOW.
IT'S OVER.
NO...
IT'S NOT OVER.
YOU'RE ALIVE?!
YOU TRIED TO
HAVE ME KILLED!
YES, I DID.
YOU'RE THE BLUE
SPIRIT--
AN ENEMY OF
THE FIRE NATION!
YOU FREED THE AVATAR.
I HAD NO CHOICE!
YOU SHOULD HAVE CHOSEN
TO ACCEPT YOUR FAILURE,
YOUR DISGRACE...
THEN AT LEAST YOU
COULD HAVE LIVED.
[GRUNTING]
IT'S TOO LATE--
IT'S DEAD.
YOU HAVE BEEN TOUCHED
BY THE MOON SPIRIT.
SOME OF ITS LIFE
IS IN YOU.
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT...
IT GAVE ME LIFE.
MAYBE I CAN
GIVE IT BACK.
NO!
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO DO THAT.
IT'S MY DUTY, SOKKA.
I WON'T LET YOU.
YOUR FATHER TOLD
ME TO PROTECT YOU!
I HAVE TO DO THIS.
[GASPS]
NO!
SHE'S GONE.
GOOD-BYE, SOKKA.
I'LL ALWAYS
BE WITH YOU.
[GRUNTING]
IT CAN'T BE!
TAKE MY HAND!
I'VE DECIDED TO GO
TO THE SOUTH POLE.
SOME OTHER BENDERS
AND HEALERS
WANT TO JOIN ME.
IT'S TIME WE
HELPED REBUILD
OUR SISTER TRIBE.
WHAT ABOUT AANG?
HE STILL NEEDS TO
LEARN WATERBENDING.
WELL--THEN HE
BETTER GET USED TO
CALLING YOU
MASTER KATARA.
THE SPIRITS
GAVE ME A VISION
WHEN YUE WAS BORN.
I SAW A BEAUTIFUL,
BRAVE YOUNG WOMAN BECOME
THE MOON SPIRIT.
I KNEW THIS DAY
WOULD COME.
YOU MUST BE PROUD.
SO PROUD...
AND SAD.
Uncle: I'M SURPRISED,
PRINCE ZUKO,
SURPRISED THAT
YOU ARE NOT
AT THIS MOMENT TRYING
TO CAPTURE THE AVATAR.
I'M TIRED.
THEN YOU SHOULD REST.
A MAN NEEDS HIS REST.
[CHITTERING]
YOU, TOO, MOMO!
COME HERE!
IROH IS A TRAITOR,
AND YOUR BROTHER ZUKO
IS A FAILURE.
I HAVE A TASK FOR YOU...
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]