Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
Katara: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
I'VE DECIDED TO GO
TO THE SOUTH POLE.
WHAT ABOUT AANG?
HE STILL NEEDS TO LEARN
WATERBENDING.
THEN HE BETTER GET
USED TO CALLING YOU
MASTER KATARA.
I'M TIRED.
THEN YOU SHOULD REST.
A MAN NEEDS HIS REST.
PRINCE ZUKO IS
A FAILURE.
I HAVE A TASK FOR YOU.
AAH!
[AANG BREATHING HEAVILY]
AANG?
DO YOU WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT?
NAH. JUST A NIGHTMARE.
I WAS IN THE AVATAR
STATE,
BUT I WAS OUTSIDE MY
BODY WATCHING MYSELF.
IT WAS SCARY.
I WAS SCARY.
KATARA, I WANT YOU
TO HAVE THIS.
THIS AMULET CONTAINS
WATER FROM
THE SPIRIT OASIS.
THE WATER HAS
UNIQUE PROPERTIES.
DON'T LOSE IT.
THANK YOU,
MASTER PAKKU.
AANG, THESE SCROLLS
WILL HELP YOU MASTER
WATERBENDING.
BUT REMEMBER,
THEY'RE
NO SUBSTITUTE FOR
A REAL MASTER.
SOKKA...
TAKE CARE, SON.
FLY STRAIGHT
TO THE EARTH KINGDOM
BASED TO
THE EAST OF HERE.
GENERAL FUNG
WILL PROVIDE YOU
WITH AN ESCORT
TO OMASHU.
THERE YOU'LL BE
SAFE TO BEGIN
YOUR EARTHBENDING
TRAINING WITH
KING BUMI.
APPA, YIP-YIP!
Katara: SAY HI
TO GRAN GRAN
FOR ME.
AHH.
THIS IS WHAT I'VE BEEN MISSING.
WHO KNEW FLOATING ON A PIECE
OF DRIFTWOOD FOR 3 WEEKS
WITH NO FOOD OR WATER
AND SEA VULTURES WAITING
TO PLUCK OUT YOUR LIVER
COULD MAKE ONE SO TENSE?
I SEE. IT'S
THE ANNIVERSARY,
ISN'T IT?
3 YEARS AGO
TODAY, I WAS BANISHED.
I LOST IT ALL.
I WANT IT BACK.
I WANT THE AVATAR.
I WANT MY HONOR,
MY THRONE.
I WANT MY FATHER NOT
TO THINK I'M WORTHLESS.
I'M SURE HE DOESN'T.
WHY WOULD HE BANISH YOU
IF HE DIDN'T CARE?
UH, THAT CAME OUT
WRONG, DIDN'T IT?
MY BROTHER AND MY UNCLE
HAVE DISGRACED
THE FIRE LORD
AND BROUGHT SHAME
ON ALL OF US.
YOU MAY HAVE MIXED FEELINGS
ABOUT ATTACKING MEMBERS
OF THE ROYAL FAMILY.
I UNDERSTAND.
BUT I ASSURE YOU,
IF YOU HESITATE, I WILL NOT
HESITATE TO BRING YOU DOWN.
DISMISSED.
PRINCESS, I'M AFRAID
THE TIDES WILL NOT
ALLOW US TO BRING
THE SHIP INTO PORT
BEFORE NIGHTFALL.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN,
BUT I DO NOT KNOW
MUCH ABOUT THE TIDES.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN
SOMETHING TO ME?
OF COURSE, YOUR HIGHNESS.
DO THE TIDES
COMMAND THIS SHIP?
I'M AFRAID
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU SAID THE TIDES
WOULD NOT ALLOW US
TO BRING THE SHIP IN.
DO THE TIDES
COMMAND THIS SHIP?
NO, PRINCESS.
AND IF I WERE TO HAVE
YOU THROWN OVERBOARD,
WOULD THE TIDES THINK
TWICE ABOUT SMASHING YOU
AGAINST THE ROCKY SHORE?
NO, PRINCESS.
WELL, THEN MAYBE YOU SHOULD
WORRY LESS ABOUT THE TIDES,
WHO HAVE ALREADY MADE UP
THEIR MIND ABOUT KILLING YOU
AND WORRY MORE ABOUT ME,
WHO'S STILL MULLING IT OVER.
I'LL PULL US IN.
THERE IT IS!
WELCOME, AVATAR AANG!
I AM GENERAL FUNG.
AND WELCOME TO ALL OF
YOU GREAT HEROES--
APPA, MOMO, BRAVE SOKKA,
THE MIGHTY KATARA.
MIGHTY KATARA? I LIKE THAT.
[FIREWORKS]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
NOT BAD. NOT BAD.
AVATAR AANG, WE WERE
ALL AMAZED
AT THE STORIES OF HOW
YOU SINGLE-HANDEDLY
WIPED OUT
AN ENTIRE FIRE NAVY FLEET
AT THE NORTH POLE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT IT FEELS LIKE TO WIELD
SUCH DEVASTATING POWER.
IT'S AN AWESOME RESPONSIBILITY.
I TRY NOT TO THINK
ABOUT IT TOO MUCH.
AVATAR, YOU'RE READY TO FACE
THE FIRE LORD NOW.
WHAT?! NO, I'M NOT.
AANG STILL NEEDS
TO MASTER ALL
4 ELEMENTS.
WHY? WITH THE KIND OF
POWER HE POSSESSES,
POWER ENOUGH TO DESTROY
HUNDREDS OF BATTLESHIPS
IN A MATTER OF MINUTES,
HE COULD DEFEAT
THE FIRE LORD NOW.
SIR, THE THING IS,
AANG CAN ONLY DO
THOSE THINGS
WHEN HE'S IN
THE AVATAR STATE.
SEE, IT'S THIS SPECIAL
STATE WHERE--
I'M WELL AWARE.
YOUR EYES
AND TATTOOS GLOW,
AND YOU'RE ABLE TO SUMMON
UNBELIEVABLE POWER.
WITHOUT YOU, WE'D BE
SLAUGHTERED BEFORE WE
EVEN REACH THEIR SHORES.
BUT WITH YOU LEADING THE WAY,
AS THE ULTIMATE WEAPON,
WE COULD CUT
A SWATH
RIGHT THROUGH
TO THE HEART OF
THE FIRE NATION.
RIGHT, BUT I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO GET IN OR OUT
OF THE AVATAR STATE,
MUCH LESS WHAT TO DO
ONCE I'M THERE.
Fung:
SO IT'S DECIDED, THEN.
I'LL HELP YOU FIGURE OUT HOW
TO GET INTO THE AVATAR STATE,
AND THEN YOU'LL FACE
YOUR DESTINY.
NO. NOTHING'S
DECIDED.
WE ALREADY HAVE
A PLAN.
AANG'S PURSUING
HIS DESTINY
HIS WAY.
Fung: WELL, WHILE YOU TAKE YOUR
TIME LEARNING THE ELEMENTS,
THE WAR GOES ON.
MAY I SHOW YOU SOMETHING?
THAT'S THE INFIRMARY.
AND THOSE SOLDIERS ARE
THE LUCKY ONES.
THEY CAME BACK.
EVERY DAY
THE FIRE NATION
TAKES LIVES.
PEOPLE ARE DYING, AANG.
YOU COULD END IT NOW.
THINK ABOUT IT.
ALMOST PERFECT.
ONE HAIR OUT OF PLACE.
ALMOST ISN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
[DISTANT THUNDER]
GENERAL FUNG?
COME IN, AANG.
HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT
OUR DISCUSSION?
I'M IN.
I'LL FIGHT
THE FIRE LORD.
I TOLD THE GENERAL
I'D HELP HIM
BY GOING INTO
THE AVATAR STATE.
AANG, NO. THIS IS
NOT THE RIGHT WAY.
WHY NOT? REMEMBER WHEN
HE TOOK OUT THE FIRE NAVY?
HE WAS INCREDIBLE.
THERE'S A RIGHT
WAY TO DO THIS--
PRACTICE, STUDY,
AND DISCIPLINE.
OR JUST GLOW IT UP
AND STOP THAT FIRE LORD.
IF YOU TWO
MEATHEADS WANT
TO THROW AWAY
EVERYTHING
WE'VE WORKED
FOR, FINE.
GO AHEAD
AND GLOW IT UP.
KATARA,
I'M JUST BEING REALISTIC!
I DON'T HAVE TIME TO
DO THIS THE RIGHT WAY.
THIS RARE CHI
ENHANCING TEA IS
A NATURAL STIMULANT.
IN AN ORDINARY WARRIOR,
IT IMPROVES STRENGTH
AND ENERGY TENFOLD.
IN YOU, IT MAY INDUCE
THE AVATAR STATE.
TENFOLD ENERGY, HUH?
Aang, speaking rapidly:
IS IT WORKING?
I CAN'T TELL! SOMEBODY TELL ME
IF I'M IN THE AVATAR STATE
BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE
A GOOD VIEW OF MYSELF.
AM I TALKING TOO LOUD?
I GUESS HE COULD TALK
THE FIRE LORD TO DEATH.
UH!
MAYBE I CAN SHOCK YOU
INTO THE AVATAR STATE.
I LOVE SURPRISES.
AAH!
STILL NOT GLOWING.
UH! UH! AAH!
YOU ARE WEARING A CEREMONIAL
PIECE OF CLOTHING
FROM EACH OF
THE BENDING NATIONS.
NOW, I WILL JOIN THE 4 ELEMENTS
INTO ONE.
WATER, EARTH, FIRE, AIR!
FOUR ELEMENTS TOGETHER AS ONE.
THIS IS JUST MUD.
SO, DO YOU FEEL ANYTHING?
AH-CHOO!
WE HAVE TO FIND A WAY.
LOOK AT THESE
MAGNIFICENT SHELLS.
I'LL ENJOY THESE KEEPSAKES
FOR YEARS TO COME.
WE DON'T NEED ANY MORE
USELESS THINGS.
YOU FORGET, WE HAVE
TO CARRY EVERYTHING
OURSELVES NOW.
HELLO, BROTHER,
UNCLE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
IN MY COUNTRY, WE
EXCHANGE A PLEASANT HELLO
BEFORE ASKING QUESTIONS.
HAVE YOU BECOME
UNCIVILIZED
SO SOON, ZUZU?
DON'T CALL ME THAT.
TO WHAT DO WE OWE
THIS HONOR?
HMM, MUST BE A FAMILY TRAIT.
BOTH OF YOU SO QUICK
TO GET TO THE POINT.
I'VE COME
WITH A MESSAGE
FROM HOME.
FATHER'S CHANGED
HIS MIND.
FAMILY IS
SUDDENLY
VERY IMPORTANT
TO HIM.
HE'S HEARD
RUMORS OF PLANS
TO OVERTHROW HIM--
TREACHEROUS PLOTS.
FAMILY ARE
THE ONLY ONES YOU
CAN REALLY TRUST.
FATHER REGRETS
YOUR BANISHMENT.
HE WANTS YOU HOME.
DID YOU HEAR ME?
YOU SHOULD BE HAPPY,
EXCITED, GRATEFUL.
I JUST GAVE YOU
GREAT NEWS.
I'M SURE YOUR BROTHER
SIMPLY NEEDS A MOMENT--
DON'T INTERRUPT,
UNCLE.
I STILL HAVEN'T HEARD
MY THANK YOU.
I'M NOT A MESSENGER.
I DIDN'T HAVE TO COME
ALL THIS WAY.
FATHER REGRETS?
HE WANTS ME BACK?
I CAN SEE YOU NEED
TIME TO TAKE THIS IN.
I'LL COME TO CALL
ON YOU TOMORROW.
GOOD EVENING.
Katara: CAN WE TALK
ABOUT SOMETHING?
Aang: SURE.
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHEN WE WERE AT
THE AIR TEMPLE
AND YOU FOUND
MONK GYATSO'S
SKELETON?
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
SO HORRIBLE AND
TRAUMATIC FOR YOU.
I SAW YOU GET
SO UPSET
THAT YOU WEREN'T
EVEN YOU ANYMORE.
I'M NOT SAYING
THE AVATAR STATE
DOESN'T HAVE INCREDIBLE
AND HELPFUL POWER.
BUT YOU HAVE
TO UNDERSTAND, FOR
THE PEOPLE WHO LOVE YOU,
WATCHING YOU BE IN
THAT MUCH RAGE AND PAIN
IS REALLY SCARY.
I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU TOLD ME THAT,
BUT I STILL NEED
TO DO THIS.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NO, YOU DON'T.
EVERY DAY, MORE
AND MORE PEOPLE DIE.
I'M ALREADY
A HUNDRED YEARS LATE.
DEFEATING THE FIRE LORD
IS THE ONLY WAY TO STOP
THIS WAR.
I HAVE TO TRY IT.
I CAN'T WATCH YOU
DO THIS TO YOURSELF.
I'M NOT COMING
TOMORROW.
GOOD NIGHT.
WE'RE GOING HOME
AFTER 3 LONG YEARS.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLE.
I HAVE NEVER KNOWN MY BROTHER
TO REGRET ANYTHING.
DID YOU LISTEN
TO AZULA?
FATHER'S REALIZED
HOW IMPORTANT
FAMILY IS TO HIM.
HE CARES ABOUT ME.
I CARE ABOUT YOU.
I MEAN, IF OZAI
WANTS YOU BACK,
WELL,
I THINK IT MAY NOT
BE FOR THE REASONS
YOU IMAGINE.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW
MY FATHER FEELS ABOUT ME.
YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING.
ZUKO, I ONLY MEANT
THAT IN OUR FAMILY,
THINGS ARE
NOT ALWAYS
WHAT THEY SEEM.
I THINK YOU ARE EXACTLY
WHAT YOU SEEM--
A LAZY, MISTRUSTFUL,
SHALLOW OLD MAN
WHO'S ALWAYS BEEN
JEALOUS OF HIS BROTHER.
AAH!
SOKKA, SOKKA,
WAKE UP.
HUH?
I DON'T THINK
WE SHOULD BE TRYING
TO BRING ON
THE AVATAR STATE.
YOU SURE?
YES.
OK.
DO YOU THINK
THE GENERAL
WILL BE MAD?
WHAT CAN HE SAY?
YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
WHO KNOWS BETTER
THAN YOU?
WAIT!
DON'T LEAVE WITHOUT ME.
UNCLE, YOU'VE
CHANGED YOUR MIND.
FAMILY STICKS
TOGETHER, RIGHT?
WE'RE FINALLY
GOING HOME.
Aang: THE THING IS,
I DON'T THINK WE'LL EVER BE
ABLE TO TRIGGER IT
ON PURPOSE.
SO I GUESS THAT'S IT.
SURE I CAN'T
CHANGE YOUR MIND?
I'M SURE. I CAN ONLY
REACH THE AVATAR STATE
WHEN I'M
IN GENUINE DANGER.
I SEE. I WAS
AFRAID YOU'D SAY THAT.
AANG!
Aang: AAH!
MEN, ATTACK THE AVATAR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I BELIEVE WE ARE
ABOUT TO GET RESULTS.
I'M NOT YOUR ENEMY.
I WON'T FIGHT YOU.
YOU CAN'T RUN
FOREVER!
YOU CAN'T FIGHT
FOREVER.
BROTHER, UNCLE,
WELCOME.
I'M SO GLAD YOU
DECIDED TO COME.
ARE WE READY
TO DEPART,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
SET OUR COURSE
FOR HOME, CAPTAIN.
HOME.
YOU HEARD
THE PRINCESS.
RAISE THE ANCHORS.
WE'RE TAKING
THE PRISONERS HOME.
YOUR HIGHNESS, I...
YOU LIED TO ME.
LIKE I'VE NEVER
DONE THAT BEFORE.
[YELLS]
AAH!
I WONDER WHAT
CRAZY THING
THEY'RE TRYING NOW.
[PURRS]
[HEAVY THUDS]
MAYBE WE SHOULD JUST
MAKE SURE AANG'S OK.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
THE GENERAL'S
GONE CRAZY.
HE'S TRYING
TO FORCE AANG
INTO THE AVATAR
STATE.
GOOD BIRD-HORSE THINGY.
MAYBE YOU CAN AVOID
ME, BUT SHE CAN'T.
I CAN'T MOVE.
DON'T HURT HER.
KATARA, NO!
WHOA!
STOP THIS! YOU HAVE
TO LET HER GO.
YOU COULD SAVE HER
IF YOU WERE IN
THE AVATAR STATE.
I'M TRYING. I'M TRYING.
AANG, I'M SINKING!
I DON'T SEE GLOWING.
AAH! PLEASE.
YOU DON'T NEED TO DO THIS.
APPARENTLY, I DO.
AAH!
IT WORKED.
IT WORKED!
AAH!
ZUKO, LET'S GO!
HYAH! HYAH! HYAH...
YOU KNOW, FATHER BLAMES
UNCLE FOR THE LOSS
OF THE NORTH POLE.
AND HE CONSIDERS YOU
A MISERABLE FAILURE
FOR NOT FINDING
THE AVATAR.
WHY WOULD HE WANT YOU
BACK HOME,
EXCEPT TO LOCK YOU UP
WHERE YOU CAN NO LONGER
EMBARRASS HIM?
[YELLING]
AAH! UH!
AVATAR AANG,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
YOUR FRIEND IS SAFE.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
IT WAS JUST
A TRICK TO TRIGGER
THE AVATAR STATE.
AND IT WORKED!
IT'S TIME
YOU LEARNED.
THE AVATAR STATE IS
A DEFENSE MECHANISM
DESIGNED
TO EMPOWER YOU WITH
THE SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE
OF ALL THE PAST AVATARS.
THE GLOW IS THE COMBINATION
OF ALL YOUR PAST LIVES
FOCUSING THEIR ENERGY
THROUGH YOUR BODY.
IN THE AVATAR STATE,
YOU ARE AT YOUR MOST POWERFUL...
BUT YOU'RE ALSO
AT YOUR MOST VULNERABLE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
IF YOU ARE KILLED IN
THE AVATAR STATE,
THE REINCARNATION CYCLE
WILL BE BROKEN
AND THE AVATAR
WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
I'M SORRY, KATARA.
I HOPE YOU NEVER HAVE
TO SEE ME LIKE THAT AGAIN.
HA! ARE YOU JOKING?
THAT WAS ALMOST PERFECT.
WE JUST HAVE TO FIND OUT
A WAY TO CONTROL YOU
WHEN YOU'RE LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE OUT OF
YOUR MIND.
I GUESS WE'LL FIGURE
IT OUT ON THE WAY
TO THE FIRE NATION.
ANYBODY GOT A PROBLEM
WITH THAT?
DO YOU STILL
WANT AN ESCORT
TO OMASHU?
I THINK WE'RE
ALL SET.
ANYONE WHO HARBORS
THESE TRAITORS
WILL FACE THE WRATH OF
THE FIRE LORD.
THERE WILL BE
NO PLACE LEFT TO HIDE.
I THINK WE'RE
SAFE HERE.
♪♪