Girl: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF!
Girl: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
GENERAL FONG
WILL PROVIDE YOU
WITH AN ESCORT
TO OMASHU.
THERE YOU'LL BE SAFE
TO BEGIN YOUR
EARTHBENDING TRAINING
WITH KING BUMI.
ANYONE WHO HARBORS
THESE TRAITORS
WILL FACE THE WRATH
OF THE FIRE LORD!
I THINK WE'RE
SAFE HERE.
Sokka: YOU GUYS
ARE GONNA BE DONE
SOON, RIGHT?
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF
GROUND TO COVER
IF WE WANT TO MAKE
IT TO OMASHU TODAY.
WHAT, LIKE YOU'RE READY
TO GO RIGHT NOW, NAKED GUY?
I COULD BE READY
IN TWO MINUTES.
SERIOUSLY. WHENEVER.
SO, YOU WERE
SHOWING ME
THE OCTOPUS
FORM.
RIGHT. LET ME SEE
YOUR STANCE.
YOUR ARMS ARE TOO FAR APART.
SEE, IF YOU MOVE THEM
CLOSER TOGETHER,
YOU PROTECT YOUR CENTER.
YOU GOT IT?
OH. YEAH.
THANKS.
OK, LET'S SEE WHAT YOU GOT.
YOU MAKE A FINE OCTOPUS,
PUPIL AANG.
[SPLASH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAN HUMMING]
♪ DON'T FALL IN LOVE ♪
♪ WITH A TRAVELING GIRL ♪
♪ SHE'LL LEAVE YOU BROKE ♪
♪ AND BROKEN-HEARTED ♪
[MUSIC STOPS]
HEY, HEY!
RIVER PEOPLE.
WE'RE NOT RIVER PEOPLE.
YOU'RE NOT?
WELL, THEN WHAT KIND
OF PEOPLE ARE YOU?
JUST PEOPLE.
AREN'T WE ALL,
BROTHER? HOO!
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M CHONG.
AND THIS IS
MY WIFE LILY.
WE'RE NOMADS.
HAPPY TO GO WHEREVER
THE WIND TAKES US.
[SINGS GIBBERISH]
YOU GUYS ARE NOMADS?!
THAT'S GREAT!
I'M A NOMAD!
HEY! ME, TOO!
I KNOW.
YOU JUST SAID THAT.
OH.
NICE UNDERWEAR.
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
I DIDN'T FIND
ANYTHING TO EAT.
I CAN'T LIVE
LIKE THIS.
I WASN'T MEANT
TO BE A FUGITIVE.
THIS IS IMPOSSIBLE!
UNCLE...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE LOOKING AT
THE RARE
WHITE DRAGON BUSH.
IT'S LEAVES MAKE A TEA
SO DELICIOUS
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
THAT, OR IT'S
THE WHITE JADE BUSH,
WHICH IS POISONOUS.
WE NEED FOOD,
NOT TEA.
I'M GOING FISHING.
HMM.
DELECTABLE TEA,
OR DEADLY POISON?
[LOWING]
Aang: HEY, SOKKA,
YOU SHOULD HEAR SOME
OF THESE STORIES.
THESE GUYS HAVE
BEEN EVERYWHERE.
WELL, NOT EVERYWHERE,
LITTLE ARROWHEAD,
BUT WHERE WE HAVEN'T BEEN,
WE'VE HEARD ABOUT
THROUGH STORIES
AND SONGS.
THEY SAID THEY'LL
TAKE US TO SEE
A GIANT
NIGHT CRAWLER.
Man: ON THE WAY,
THERE'S A WATERFALL
THAT CREATES
A NEVER-ENDING RAINBOW!
LOOK, I HATE TO BE
THE WET BLANKET HERE,
BUT SINCE KATARA IS BUSY,
I GUESS IT'S UP TO ME.
WE NEED TO GET TO OMASHU.
NO SIDETRACKS, NO WORMS,
AND DEFINITELY
NO RAINBOWS.
WHOA!
SOUNDS LIKE SOMEONE'S
GOT A CASE OF
DESTINATION FEVER.
HA HA.
YOU'RE WORRIED
TOO MUCH ABOUT
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
Lily: YOU GOTTA FOCUS
LESS ON THE WHERE
AND MORE ON THE GOING.
OH...
MA..
SHU!
SOKKA'S RIGHT.
WE NEED TO FIND
KING BUMI
SO AANG CAN LEARN
EARTHBENDING
SOMEWHERE SAFE.
WELL, SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE
HEADED TO OMASHU.
THERE'S AN OLD STORY
ABOUT A SECRET PASS...
RIGHT THROUGH THE MOUNTAINS.
IS THIS REAL
OR A LEGEND?
OH, IT'S A REAL LEGEND.
AND IT'S AS OLD AS
EARTHBENDING ITSELF.
[STRUMMING]
[HUMMING]
♪ TWO LOVERS ♪
♪ FORBIDDEN FROM
ONE ANOTHER ♪
♪ A WAR DIVIDES THEIR PEOPLE ♪
♪ AND A MOUNTAIN DIVIDES
THEM APART ♪
♪ BUILT A PATH TO BE TOGETHER ♪
YEAH, I FORGET
THE NEXT COUPLE LINES,
BUT THEN IT GOES...
♪ SECRET TUNNEL ♪
♪ THROUGH THE MOUNTAIN ♪
♪ SECRET, SECRET, SECRET,
SECRET TUNNEL ♪
♪ YEAH ♪
[APPLAUSE]
I THINK WE'LL JUST
STICK WITH FLYING.
WE'VE DEALT WITH
THE FIRE NATION BEFORE.
WE'LL BE FINE.
YEAH, THANKS
FOR THE HELP,
BUT APPA HATES
GOING UNDERGROUND.
AND WE NEED TO DO
WHATEVER MAKES APPA
MOST COMFORTABLE.
[LOWING]
LAUNCH!
[SNARLING]
[SCREAMING]
SECRET LOVE CAVE.
LET'S GO.
Iroh: ZUKO,
REMEMBER THAT PLANT
I THOUGHT
MIGHT BE TEA?
YOU DIDN'T.
I DID.
AND IT WASN'T.
AAGH!
WHEN THE RASH SPREADS
TO MY THROAT,
I WILL STOP
BREATHING.
BUT LOOK WHAT I FOUND!
THESE ARE PAKUI BERRIES.
KNOWN TO CURE THE POISON
OF THE WHITE JADE PLANT!
THAT, OR MAKAOLA BERRIES,
THAT CAUSE BLINDNESS.
WE'RE NOT TAKING
ANY MORE CHANCES
WITH THESE PLANTS!
WE NEED TO GET HELP.
BUT WHERE ARE
WE GOING TO GO?
WE'RE ENEMIES OF
THE EARTH KINGDOM,
AND FUGITIVES FROM
THE FIRE NATION.
IF THE EARTH KINGDOM
DISCOVERS US,
THEY'LL HAVE
US KILLED.
BUT IF THE FIRE NATION
DISCOVERS US,
WE'LL BE TURNED OVER TO AZULA.
EARTH KINGDOM
IT IS.
Sokka: HOW FAR ARE WE
FROM THE TUNNEL?
ACTUALLY, IT'S NOT
JUST ONE TUNNEL.
THE LOVERS DIDN'T
WANT ANYONE
TO FIND OUT ABOUT
THEIR LOVE,
SO THEY BUILT
A WHOLE LABYRINTH.
LABYRINTH?!
I'M SURE WE'LL
FIGURE IT OUT.
ALL YOU NEED TO
DO IS TRUST IN LOVE,
ACCORDING TO
THE CURSE.
[GROWLS]
CURSE?!
Chong: HEY, HEY!
WE'RE HERE!
Sokka: WHAT EXACTLY
IS THIS CURSE?
THE CURSE SAYS THAT ONLY
THOSE THAT TRUST IN LOVE
CAN MAKE IT THROUGH THE CAVES.
OTHERWISE, YOU'LL BE
TRAPPED IN THEM FOREVER.
AND DIE.
OH, YEAH, AND DIE.
HEY!
I JUST REMEMBERED
THE REST OF THAT SONG.
[STRUMS]
♪ AND DIE ♪
THAT'S IT!
THERE'S NO WAY
WE'RE GOING THROUGH
SOME CURSED HOLE!
HEY!
SOMEONE'S MAKING
A BIG CAMPFIRE!
THAT'S NO
CAMPFIRE, MOKU.
IT'S FIRE NATION.
THEY'RE TRACKING US.
SO, ALL YOU NEED IS
TO TRUST IN LOVE
TO GET THROUGH
THESE CAVES?
THAT IS CORRECT,
MASTER ARROWHEAD.
WE CAN MAKE IT.
EVERYONE
INTO THE HOLE.
[SNARLS]
Man: HOLD ON!
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
HAVEN'T YOU HEARD
THE SONG?
JUST CLOSE THEM IN.
THE MOUNTAIN WILL
TAKE CARE OF THE REST.
[GROWLING]
Katara:
IT'S OK, APPA.
WE'LL BE FINE.
I HOPE.
WE WILL BE FINE.
ALL WE NEED
IS A PLAN.
CHONG, HOW LONG TO
THOSE TORCHES LAST?
UM, ABOUT TWO
HOURS EACH.
AND WE HAVE 5 TORCHES,
SO, THAT'S 10 HOURS.
IT DOESN'T
WORK LIKE THAT
IF THEY'RE ALL LIT
AT THE SAME TIME!
OH!
RIGHT.
I'M GONNA MAKE A MAP
TO KEEP TRACK OF
EXACTLY WHERE
WE'VE BEEN.
THEN WE SHOULD
BE ABLE TO
SOLVE IT LIKE A MAZE
AND GET THROUGH.
[APPA GROWLS]
Woman: YOU TWO MUST NOT
BE FROM AROUND HERE.
WE KNOW BETTER THAN TO
TOUCH THE WHITE JADE.
MUCH LESS MAKE IT
INTO TEA AND DRINK IT.
HA HA HA.
OOPS!
SO, WHERE ARE YOU
TRAVELING FROM?
YES, WE'RE
TRAVELLERS.
DO YOU HAVE NAMES?
NAMES?
OF COURSE WE
HAVE NAMES.
I'M...LEE.
AND THIS IS
MY UNCLE...
UH, MUSHI.
YES, MY NEPHEW WAS NAMED
AFTER HIS FATHER,
SO JUST CALL
HIM JUNIOR.
MUSHI AND JUNIOR, HUH?
MY NAME IS SONG.
YOU TWO LOOK LIKE YOU
COULD USE A GOOD MEAL.
WHY DON'T YOU STAY
FOR DINNER.
SORRY, BUT WE NEED
TO BE MOVING ON.
THAT'S TOO BAD.
MY MOM ALWAYS MAKES
TOO MUCH ROAST DUCK.
WHERE DO
YOU LIVE EXACTLY?!
SOKKA, THIS IS
THE TENTH DEAD END
YOU'VE LED US TO.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
WE ALREADY CAME
THROUGH THIS WAY.
Chong: WE DON'T
NEED A MAP.
WE JUST NEED LOVE.
THE LITTLE GUY KNOWS IT.
YEAH,
BUT I WOULDN'T
MIND A MAP ALSO.
Sokka: THERE'S
SOMETHING STRANGE HERE.
THERE'S ONLY ONE
EXPLANATION:
THE TUNNELS ARE CHANGING.
[RUMBLING]
[CHITTERING]
MY DAUGHTER TELLS ME
YOU'RE REFUGEES.
WE WERE ONCE
REFUGEES OURSELVES.
WHEN I WAS
A LITTLE GIRL,
THE FIRE NATION RAIDED
OUR FARMING VILLAGE.
ALL THE MEN WERE TAKEN AWAY.
THAT WAS THE LAST TIME
I SAW MY FATHER.
I HAVEN'T SEEN
MY FATHER
IN MANY YEARS.
OH.
IS HE FIGHTING
IN THE WAR?
YEAH.
Chong: THE TUNNELS...
THEY'RE A-CHANGING.
IT MUST BE THE CURSE.
I KNEW WE SHOULDN'T
HAVE COME DOWN HERE.
RIGHT.
IF ONLY WE'D
LISTENED TO YOU.
Katara:
EVERYONE BE QUIET.
LISTEN!
[WAILING]
[SNARLING]
A GIANT FLYING
THING WITH TEETH!
NO! IT'S A WOLF-BAT!
[ROARS]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
[PANTING]
[SCREAMING]
YEAH, IT'S NO USE.
WE'RE SEPARATED.
BUT AT LEAST
YOU HAVE US.
HA HA.
[SCREAMS]
CAN I JOIN YOU?
I KNOW WHAT YOU'VE
BEEN THROUGH.
WE'VE ALL BEEN
THROUGH IT.
THE FIRE NATION
HAS HURT YOU.
IT'S OK.
THEY'VE
HURT ME, TOO.
[STRUMMING UPBEAT TUNE]
♪ OH, DON'T
LET THE CAVE-IN
GET YOU DOWN ♪
♪ DON'T LET
THE FALLING ROCKS ♪
♪ TURN YOUR SMILE
INTO A FROWN ♪
♪ WHEN THE TUNNEL'S
AS DARK AS THAT'S ♪
♪ WHEN YOU NEED A CLOWN ♪
♪ HEY ♪
♪ DON'T LET THE CAVE-IN
GET YOU DOWN, SOKKA ♪
AANG, LOOK!
Aang: WE FOUND THE EXIT!
[STRAINING]
[APPA GROWLS]
[SCREAMING]
THIS ISN'T THE EXIT.
NO.
IT'S A TOMB.
Aang: IT MUST BE THE TWO
LOVERS FROM THE LEGEND.
THAT'S WHO IS BURIED HERE.
THESE PICTURES
TELL THEIR STORY.
Katara: THEY MET
ON TOP OF THE MOUNTAIN
THAT DIVIDED THEIR TWO VILLAGES.
THE VILLAGES WERE ENEMIES,
SO THEY COULD NOT
BE TOGETHER.
BUT THEIR LOVE WAS STRONG,
AND THEY FOUND A WAY.
THE TWO LOVERS LEARNED
EARTHBENDING
FROM THE BADGER-MOLES.
THEY BECAME THE FIRST
EARTHBENDERS.
THEY BUILT ELABORATE TUNNELS
SO THAT THEY COULD
MEET SECRETLY.
ANYONE WHO TRIED
TO FOLLOW THEM
WOULD BE LOST FOREVER
IN THE LABYRINTH.
BUT ONE DAY,
THE MAN DIDN'T COME.
HE DIED IN THE WAR BETWEEN
THEIR TWO VILLAGES.
DEVASTATED, THE WOMAN
UNLEASHED A TERRIBLE DISPLAY
OF HER EARTHBENDING POWER.
SHE COULD HAVE
DESTROYED THEM ALL...
BUT INSTEAD SHE DECLARED
THE WAR OVER.
BOTH VILLAGES HELPED
HER BUILD A NEW CITY
WHERE THEY WOULD LIVE
TOGETHER IN PEACE.
THE WOMAN'S NAME WAS OMA,
AND THE MAN'S NAME WAS SHU.
THE GREAT CITY
WAS NAMED OMASHU
AS A MONUMENT TO THEIR LOVE.
"LOVE IS BRIGHTEST
IN THE DARK."
Moku: OH, GREAT!
YOUR PLANS HAVE LED US
TO ANOTHER DEAD END.
Sokka: AT LEAST I'M
THINKING OF IDEAS
AND TRYING TO GET IS
OUT OF HERE, MOKU.
WHOA, WHOA.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WE'RE THINKING OF IDEAS?
'CAUSE I'VE HAD AN IDEA
FOR, LIKE, AN HOUR NOW.
YES!
WE'RE ALL THINKING
OF IDEAS!
WELL, THEN
LISTEN TO THIS.
IF LOVE IS THE KEY
OUT OF HERE,
THEN ALL WE NEED TO DO
IS PLAY A LOVE SONG.
[STRUMMING]
Aang: HOW ARE WE GONNA
FIND OUR WAY OUT
OF THESE TUNNELS?
I HAVE A CRAZY IDEA.
WHAT?
NEVER MIND.
IT'S TOO CRAZY.
KATARA,
WHAT IS IT?
I WAS THINKING...
THE CURSE SAYS WE'LL BE
TRAPPED IN HERE FOREVER
UNLESS WE TRUST IN LOVE.
RIGHT.
AND HERE IT SAYS "LOVE
IS BRIGHTEST IN THE DARK"
AND HAS A PICTURE
OF THEM KISSING.
WHERE ARE YOU
GOING WITH THIS?
WELL...
WHAT IF WE KISSED?
US, KISSING?
SEE? IT WAS A CRAZY IDEA.
US...
KISSING.
[SCOFFS]
US, KISSING.
WHAT WAS I THINKING?!
CAN YOU IMAGINE THAT?
YEAH. HA HA.
I DEFINITELY WOULDN'T
WANT TO KISS YOU.
OH.
WELL, I DIDN'T REALIZE
IT WAS SUCH
A HORRIBLE OPTION.
SORRY I SUGGESTED IT.
NO, NO. I MEAN...
IF IT WAS A CHOICE
BETWEEN KISSING YOU
AND DYING...
OH!
WHAT?!
I'M SAYING
I WOULD RATHER
KISS YOU THAN DIE.
THAT'S A COMPLIMENT.
WELL, I'M NOT SURE
WHICH I WOULD RATHER DO.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH ME?
[STRUMMING TUNE]
♪ EVEN IF YOU'RE LOST ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T LOSE THE LOVE ♪
♪ BECAUSE IT'S
IN YOUR HEART ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH ♪
Iroh: THANK YOU
FOR THE DUCK.
IT WAS EXCELLENT.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
IT BRINGS ME JOY
TO SEE SOMEONE
EAT MY COOKING
WITH SUCH GUSTO.
MUCH PRACTICE.
JUNIOR, WHERE
ARE YOU MANNERS?
YOU NEED TO THANK
THESE NICE PEOPLE.
THANK YOU.
Song: I KNOW
YOU DON'T THINK
THERE'S ANY HOPE
LEFT IN THE WORLD,
BUT THERE IS HOPE.
THE AVATAR
HAS RETURNED.
I KNOW.
[LOWING]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
THESE PEOPLE JUST
SHOWED YOU GREAT KINDNESS.
THEY'RE ABOUT
TO SHOW US
A LITTLE MORE
KINDNESS.
WELL?
Aang: WE'RE GONNA
RUN OUT OF LIGHT
ANY SECOND NOW,
AREN'T WE?
I THINK SO.
THEN, WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO?
WHAT CAN WE DO?
[STRUMMING]
[GROWLING]
[SNARLING]
[SCREAMING]
Chong: HEY!
YOU SAVED US, SOKKA!
NO.
THEY WERE TRYING TO GET
AWAY FROM SOMETHING.
FROM WHAT?
[RUMBLING]
[GROWLING]
AAGH!
OOF!
♪
♪♪♪
♪♪
HEY, THOSE THINGS
ARE MUSIC-LOVERS!
♪ BADGER-MOLES
COMING TOWARDS ME ♪
♪ COME ON, GUYS ♪
♪ HELP ME OUT ♪
♪ THE BIG BAD BADGER-MOLES ♪
♪ WHO OPENED THE TUNNELS ♪
♪ HATE THE WOLF-BATS ♪
♪ BUT LOVE THE SOUNDS ♪
Aang: IT'S MADE OF
SOME KIND OF CRYSTALS.
THEY MUST ONLY LIGHT
UP IN THE DARK.
THAT'S HOW
THE TWO LOVERS
FOUND EACH OTHER.
THEY JUST PUT OUT
THEIR LIGHTS
AND FOLLOWED
THE CRYSTALS.
THAT MUST BE THE WAY OUT!
SO, UM...
LET'S GO!
[GROWLS]
WHAT ABOUT SOKKA?!
[RUMBLING]
[SNARLING]
SOKKA!
HOW DID YOU
GUYS GET OUT?!
JUST LIKE
THE LEGEND SAYS--
WE LET LOVE
LEAD THE WAY.
REALLY?
WE LET HUGE
FEROCIOUS BEASTS
LEAD OUR WAY.
[GROWLING]
[CHITTERING]
[ROARS]
WHY IS YOUR
FOREHEAD ALL RED?
NOBODY REACT TO WHAT
I'M ABOUT TO TELL YOU.
I THINK THAT KID
MIGHT BE THE AVATAR.
Aang: SO, ARE YOU GUYS
GONNA COME TO
OMASHU WITH US?
NOPE.
OK.
THANKS FOR
EVERYTHING, MOKU.
SOKKA,
I HOPE YOU LEARNED
A LITTLE SOMETHING
ABOUT NOT LETTING
THE PLANS
GET IN THE WAY
OF THE JOURNEY.
JUST PLAY
YOUR SONGS.
HEY! GOOD PLAN!
[STRUMMING]
♪ EVEN IF YOU'RE LOST ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T LOSE THE LOVE ♪
♪ BECAUSE
IT'S IN YOUR HEART ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH ♪
Sokka: THE JOURNEY
WAS LONG AND ANNOYING,
BUT NOW YOU GET TO SEE
WHAT IT'S REALLY ABOUT--
THE DESTINATION.
I PRESENT TO YOU
THE EARTH KINGDOM
CITY OF O--
OH, NO!
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]