Girl: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF!
Girl: BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
ANYONE WHO HARBORS
THESE TRAITORS
WILL FACE THE WRATH
OF THE FIRE LORD.
WE NEED TO FIND
KING BUMI SO
AANG CAN LEARN
EARTHBENDING
SOMEWHERE SAFE.
WELL, SOUNDS LIKE
YOU'RE HEADED TO OMASHU.
I PRESENT TO YOU
THE EARTH KINGDOM CITY OF OM--
OH, NO.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I KNOW THE WAR
HAS SPREAD FAR,
BUT OMASHU
ALWAYS SEEMED...
UNTOUCHABLE.
Sokka:
UP UNTIL NOW,
IT WAS.
NOW, BA SING SE
IS THE ONLY GREAT
EARTH KINGDOM
STRONGHOLD LEFT.
Katara: THIS IS HORRIBLE.
BUT WE HAVE TO MOVE ON.
NO.
I'M GOING IN
TO FIND BUMI.
Sokka:
AANG, STOP!
WE DON'T EVEN
KNOW IF BUMI'S
STILL...
WHAT?
IF HE'S STILL WHAT?
AROUND.
I KNOW YOU HAD
YOUR HEART
SET ON BUMI,
BUT THERE ARE
OTHER PEOPLE
WHO CAN TEACH YOU
EARTHBENDING.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT
FINDING A TEACHER.
THIS IS ABOUT
FINDING MY FRIEND.
[GROWLING]
Sokka: A SECRET PASSAGE?
WHY DIDN'T WE JUST
USE THIS LAST TIME?
UGH!
DOES THAT ANSWER
YOUR QUESTION?
EW!
[RETCHING]
THAT WASN'T AS BAD
AS I THOUGHT.
[SCREAMING]
AAGH!
THEY WON'T LET GO!
HELP!
[GRUNTING]
STOP MAKING
SO MUCH NOISE.
IT'S JUST
A PURPLE PENTAPUS.
[GROANING]
OH.
Man: HEY!
WHAT ARE YOU KIDS
DOING OUT PAST CURFEW?
Katara: SORRY.
WE WERE JUST
ON OUR WAY HOME.
WAIT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH HIM?
UH...
HE HAS PENTAPOX, SIR.
UM, IT'S HIGHLY
CONTAGIOUS.
[GROANING]
IT'S SO AWFUL!
I'M DYING!
Katara:
AND DEADLY.
HEY, I THINK I'VE
HEARD OF PENTAPOX.
DIDN'T YOUR COUSIN
CHANG DIE OF IT?
WE BETTER GO
WASH OUR HANDS.
AND BURN OUR CLOTHES.
[COUGHING]
THANK YOU, SEWER FRIEND!
Woman: WHEN TRACKING
YOUR BROTHER AND UNCLE,
TRAVELING WITH
THE ROYAL PROCESSION
MAY NO LONGER
BE AN OPTION.
BE WISE.
Both: IF YOU HOPE TO KEEP
THE ELEMENT OF SURPRISE.
Woman: YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE ROYAL PROCESSION
IS DEAD WEIGHT.
IF I WANT TO
CATCH MY PREY,
I MUST BE AGILE, NIMBLE.
I NEED A SMALL,
ELITE TEAM.
IT'S TIME TO VISIT
SOME OLD FRIENDS.
Katara:
LET'S FIND BUMI
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
WHERE WOULD THEY
BE KEEPING HIM?
SOMEWHERE HE
CAN'T EARTHBEND.
SOMEWHERE MADE OF METAL.
THERE REALLY
IS NO FATHOMING
THE DEPTHS OF MY HATRED
FOR THIS PLACE.
MAI, YOUR FATHER WAS
APPOINTED GOVERNOR.
WE'RE LIKE
ROYALTY HERE.
BE HAPPY
AND ENJOY IT.
Man: THE TARGETS
ARE APPROACHING.
TAKE THEM OUT.
I THOUGHT MY LIFE WAS
BORING IN THE FIRE NATION,
BUT THIS PLACE IS
UNBEARABLY BLEAK.
NOTHING EVER HAPPENS.
[RUMBLING]
THE RESISTANCE!
[GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
[SIGHS]
TY LEE,
COULD THAT
POSSIBLY BE YOU?
AZULA!
IT IS SO GOOD
TO SEE YOU!
PLEASE, DON'T LET
ME INTERRUPT YOUR...
WHATEVER IT IS
YOU WERE DOING.
TELL ME...
WHAT IS THE DAUGHTER
OF A NOBLEMAN
DOING HERE?
CERTAINLY OUR
PARENTS DIDN'T SEND US
TO THE ROYAL FIRE
ACADEMY FOR GIRLS
TO END UP IN PLACES
LIKE THIS.
I HAVE A PROPOSITION
FOR YOU.
I'M HUNTING A TRAITOR.
YOU REMEMBER MY OLD
FUDDY-DUDDY UNCLE,
DON'T YOU?
OH, YEAH.
HE WAS SO FUNNY.
I WOULD BE HONORED
IF YOU WOULD JOIN ME
ON MY MISSION.
OH, I, UH...
WOULD LOVE TO.
BUT THE TRUTH IS
I'M REALLY HAPPY HERE.
I MEAN, MY AURA HAS
NEVER BEEN PINKER.
I'LL TAKE
YOUR WORD FOR IT.
WELL, I WOULDN'T
WANT YOU TO GIVE UP
THE LIFE YOU LOVE
JUST TO PLEASE ME.
THANK YOU, AZULA.
OF COURSE,
BEFORE I LEAVE,
I'M GOING TO
CATCH YOUR SHOW.
[GASPS]
UH, YEAH, SURE.
OF COURSE.
Aang: SO,
IS KING BUMI
WITH YOU GUYS?
IS HE LEADING
THE RESISTANCE?
OF COURSE NOT.
THE DAY OF THE INVASION,
WE READIED OURSELVES
FOR BATTLE.
WE WERE PREPARED
TO DEFEND OUR CITY,
TO FIGHT FOR OUR LIVES
AND FOR OUR FREEDOM.
BUT BEFORE WE EVEN
HAD A CHANCE,
KING BUMI SURRENDERED.
THE DAY OF THE INVASION,
I ASKED KING BUMI
WHAT HE WANTED TO DO.
HE LOOKED ME
IN THE EYE AND SAID...
I'M GOING TO
DO NOTHING.
HA HA HA HA!
[SNORT]
HA HA HA.
IT DOESN'T MATTER NOW.
FIGHTING THE FIRE NATION
IS THE ONLY
PATH TO FREEDOM.
AND FREEDOM
IS WORTH DYING FOR.
ACTUALLY, THERE'S
ANOTHER PATH TO FREEDOM.
YOU COULD LEAVE OMASHU.
YOU'RE DIRECTING
ALL YOUR ENERGY
TO FIGHT
THE FIRE NATION,
BUT YOU'RE
OUTNUMBERED.
YOU CAN'T WIN.
NOW IS THE TIME
TO RETREAT
SO YOU CAN LIVE TO
FIGHT ANOTHER DAY.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THEY'VE TAKEN OUR HOME,
AND WE HAVE TO FIGHT
THEM AT ANY COST!
I DON'T KNOW, YALO.
LIVING TO FIGHT
ANOTHER DAY
IS STARTING TO SOUND
PRETTY GOOD TO ME.
YEAH, I'M WITH
THE KID.
[MEN MURMURING]
FINE.
BUT THERE'S THOUSANDS
OF CITIZENS
THAT NEED TO LEAVE.
HOW ARE WE GONNA
GET THEM ALL OUT?
SUCKERS!
[COOING]
YOU'RE ALL ABOUT
TO COME DOWN
WITH A NASTY CASE
OF PENTAPOX.
[GRUNTING]
Sokka: THE MARKS
MAKE YOU LOOK SICK,
BUT YOU GOTTA
ACT SICK, TOO!
YOU GOTTA SELL IT.
[GROANING]
NOW, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YEARS OF PRACTICE.
OK, EVERYONE,
INTO SICK FORMATION!
[COOING]
AANG, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
AREN'T YOU COMING WITH US?
NO.
I'M NOT LEAVING
UNTIL I FIND BUMI.
SORRY, MOMO.
I'LL FEED YOU LATER.
[PEOPLE GROANING]
PLAGUE!
[CLANGING]
WHAT IS GOING
ON DOWN THERE?!
I SAW SOME KIDS
YESTERDAY
WHO WERE SICK
WITH PENTAPOX.
IT MUST HAVE
SPREAD.
PENTAPOX!
HMM. I'M PRETTY SURE
I'VE HEARD OF THAT.
Woman: OH,
THIS IS TERRIBLE.
Guard:
WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
Governor: DRIVE THEM
OUT OF THE CITY,
BUT DON'T TOUCH THEM.
WE HAVE TO RID THE CITY
OF THIS DISEASE.
FIRE FLAKES, DAD?
[GASPS]
HOW AWFUL!
[PANTING]
FLOPSY!
[CHUCKLES]
COME ON, FLOPSY.
YOU GOTTA HELP ME
FIND BUMI.
YIP, YIP!
OH, I GUESS THAT
DOESN'T WORK WITH YOU.
LET'S GO.
[COOING]
[BABY GIGGLING]
[CHITTERING]
[GIGGLING]
WHOA!
WEE!
[CHITTERING]
[PEOPLE GROANING]
WE'RE DEEPLY HONORED
TO HAVE THE FIRE LORD'S
DAUGHTER
AT OUR HUMBLE CIRCUS.
AND TELL US
IF THERE'S ANYTHING
WE CAN DO TO MAKE
THE SHOW MORE ENJOYABLE.
I WILL.
INCREDIBLE.
DO YOU THINK
SHE'LL FALL?
OF COURSE NOT.
THEN WOULDN'T
IT MAKE IT MORE
INTERESTING
IF YOU REMOVED
THE NET?
UH, THE THING IS...
THE PERFORMERS--
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S BEEN DONE.
I KNOW.
SET THE NET ON FIRE.
OF COURSE, PRINCESS.
BRILLIANT.
JUST BRILLIANT.
OOH!
WHAT KIND OF
DANGEROUS ANIMALS
DO YOU HAVE?
WELL, OUR CIRCUS BOASTS
THE MOST EXOTIC ASSORTMENT--
RELEASE THEM ALL!
[ELEPHANT TRUMPETS]
[TIGER ROARS]
WE LOOKED EVERYWHERE.
NO BUMI.
[MOANS]
Man: WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
WE JUST DID A HEAD COUNT.
Katara: OH, NO.
DID SOMEONE GET
LEFT BEHIND?
NO.
WE HAVE
AN EXTRA.
[WEEPING]
Governor: SO, THE RESISTANCE
HAS KIDNAPPED MY SON.
EVERYTHING IS
SO CLEVER, SO TRICKY--
JUST LIKE THEIR
KING BUMI.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO DO, SIR?
WHAT AN EXQUISITE
PERFORMANCE.
I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
HOW YOU'LL TOP
YOURSELF TOMORROW.
I'M SORRY, AZULA,
BUT UNFORTUNATELY THERE
WON'T BE A SHOW TOMORROW.
REALLY?
THE UNIVERSE IS GIVING
ME STRONG HINTS
THAT IT'S TIME FOR
A CAREER CHANGE.
I WANT TO JOIN YOU
ON YOUR MISSION.
[COOING]
NO!
BAD FIRE NATION BABY.
WAAH!
OH, ALL RIGHT.
[COOING]
OH, YOU'RE
SO CUTE!
OOH!
SURE, HE'S CUTE NOW.
BUT WHEN HE'S OLDER,
HE'LL JOIN
THE FIRE NATION ARMY.
YOU WON'T THINK
HE'S SO CUTE THEN.
HE'LL BE A KILLER.
DOES THAT LOOK
LIKE THE FACE OF
A KILLER TO YOU?
[SQUAWKING]
A MESSENGER HAWK.
Aang: IT'S FROM THE FIRE
NATION GOVERNOR.
HE THINKS WE
KIDNAPPED HIS SON.
SO, HE WANTS TO
MAKE A TRADE.
HIS SON...
FOR KING BUMI!
Sokka: YOU REALIZE
WE'RE PROBABLY
WALKING RIGHT
INTO A TRAP.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I'M SURE THE GOVERNOR
WANTS HIS SON BACK
AS MUCH AS WE
WANT BUMI.
IT'S A NEW DAY.
I HAVE A GOOD
FEELING ABOUT THIS.
PLEASE TELL ME YOU'RE
HERE TO KILL ME.
[CHUCKLES]
IT'S GREAT TO
SEE YOU, MAI.
I THOUGHT YOU RAN OFF
AND JOINED THE CIRCUS.
YOU SAID IT WAS
YOUR CALLING.
WELL, AZULA CALLED
A LITTLE LOUDER.
I HAVE A MISSION,
AND I NEED YOU BOTH.
COUNT ME IN.
ANYTHING TO GET ME
OUT OF THIS PLACE.
Governor: I APOLOGIZE.
YOU'VE COME TO OMASHU
AT A DIFFICULT TIME.
AT NOON, WE'RE
MAKING A TRADE
WITH THE RESISTANCE
TO GET TOM-TOM BACK.
YES, I'M SO SORRY TO
HEAR ABOUT YOUR SON.
BUT, REALLY,
WHAT DID YOU EXPECT
BY JUST LETTING ALL
THE CITIZENS LEAVE?
MY FATHER HAS TRUSTED
YOU WITH THIS CITY,
AND YOU'RE MAKING
A MESS OF THINGS.
FORGIVE ME, PRINCESS.
YOU STAY HERE.
MAI WILL HANDLE
THE HOSTAGE TRADE
SO YOU DON'T HAVE
A CHANCE TO MESS IT UP.
AND THERE IS
NO MORE OMASHU.
I AM RENAMING IT
IN HONOR OF MY FATHER.
THE CITY OF NEW OZAI!
[CHUCKLING]
HI, EVERYBODY!
YOU BROUGHT
MY BROTHER?
Aang:
HE'S HERE.
WE'RE READY
TO TRADE.
I'M SORRY,
BUT A THOUGHT
JUST OCCURRED TO ME.
DO YOU MIND?
OF COURSE NOT,
PRINCESS AZULA.
WE'RE TRADING
A TWO-YEAR-OLD
FOR A KING--
A POWERFUL
EARTHBENDING KING.
IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM
LIKE A FAIR TRADE.
DOES IT?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE DEAL'S OFF.
WHOA!
SEE YOU ALL LATER!
HA HA HA HA.
[SNORT]
HA HA HA.
Aang: BUMI!
[GRUNTS]
THE AVATAR.
MY LUCKY DAY.
AANG! IS THAT YOU?
WHERE DID YOU
COME FROM?
HANG ON.
WE'RE GONNA GET
YOU OUT OF HERE.
WE'VE GOTTA GET
THE BABY OUT OF HERE!
WAY AHEAD OF YOU.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
AANG!
STOP YOUR BLOWING
FOR A MINUTE.
[GROWLING]
Bumi: NOW HOLD
ON JUST A--
AAGH!
[LAUGHING]
IT'S JUST LIKE
OLD TIMES,
ISN'T IT, BUMI?
AANG, I NEED
TO TALK TO YOU!
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU, TOO!
AAGH!
PHEW!
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
HOW ARE YOU GONNA FIGHT
WITHOUT YOUR BENDING?
[GASPS]
[GRUNTS]
I SEEM TO MANAGE!
[SCREAMS]
THERE'S AANG!
WE CAN CATCH HIM!
HANG ON, BUMI!
OUR RIDE'S HERE!
[GRUNTING]
AANG!
OOF!
[GRUNTS]
YOU COULD EARTHBEND...
ALL ALONG?!
WELL, THEY DIDN'T
COVER MY FACE.
[GRUNTS]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
FREE YOURSELF?
WHY DID YOU SURRENDER
WHEN OMASHU WAS INVADED?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU, BUMI?!
LISTEN TO ME, AANG.
THERE ARE OPTIONS IN
FIGHTING CALLED JING.
IT'S A CHOICE OF HOW
YOU DIRECT YOUR ENERGY.
I KNOW!
THERE'S POSITIVE JING
WHEN YOU'RE ATTACKING,
AND NEGATIVE JING WHEN
YOU'RE RETREATING.
AND NEUTRAL JING:
WHEN YOU DO NOTHING.
THERE ARE 3 JINGS?
WELL, TECHNICALLY,
THERE ARE 85.
BUT LET'S JUST FOCUS
ON THE THIRD.
NEUTRAL JING IS THE KEY
TO EARTHBENDING.
IT INVOLVES
LISTENING AND WAITING
FOR THE RIGHT
MOMENT TO STRIKE.
THAT'S WHY
YOU SURRENDERED,
ISN'T IT?
YES, AND IT'S WHY
I CAN'T LEAVE NOW.
I GUESS I NEED TO
FIND SOMEONE ELSE
TO TEACH ME
EARTHBENDING.
YOUR TEACHER
WILL BE SOMEONE
WHO HAS MASTERED
NEUTRAL JING.
YOU NEED TO FIND SOMEONE
WHO WAITS AND LISTENS
BEFORE STRIKING.
[COOING]
HEY, MOMO.
MOMO'S MASTERED
A FEW JINGS HIMSELF.
[SQUEALS]
GOOD-BYE, AANG.
I'LL SEE YOU WHEN
THE TIME IS RIGHT.
[LAUGHING]
[SNORTING]
SO, WE'RE TRACKING DOWN
YOUR BROTHER AND UNCLE, HUH?
IT'LL BE INTERESTING
SEEING ZUKO AGAIN,
WON'T IT, MAI?
IT'S NOT
JUST ZUKO
AND IROH
ANYMORE.
WE HAVE A THIRD
TARGET NOW.
[COOING]
[GURGLING]
[GASPS]
TOM-TOM!
[MEN CHANTING RHYTHMICALLY]