[Katara]
Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations lived
together in harmony.
Then everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar, master of all
four elements, could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
100 years passed, and my brother
and I discovered the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang.
And although his airbending
skills are great,
he has a lot to learn
before he's ready
to save anyone.
Ugh!
[Katara]
But I believe Aang
can save the world.
♪♪
We're enemies of
the Earth Kingdom,
and fugitives from
the Fire Nation.
I'll always
be with you.
I lost my mother
in a Fire Nation raid.
This necklace is all
I have left of her.
I guess I need to
find someone else
to teach me
earthbending.
You need to find
someone who waits
and listens
before striking.
♪♪
Spare coins
for weary travelers?
[coins clink]
This is humiliating.
We're royalty.
These people should be
giving us whatever we want.
They will
if you ask nicely.
Spare change
for a hungry old man?
Aw, here you go.
The coin is appreciated
but not as much as your smile.
[giggles]
How about some entertainment
in exchange for...
a gold piece?
We're not performers.
Not professional, anyway.
♪ It's a long, long way
to Ba Sing Se, ♪
♪ But the girls in the city,
they look so pretty. ♪
Come on, we're talking
a gold piece here.
Let's see some action.
Dance.
♪ They kiss so sweet
that you really have to meet ♪
♪ The girls
from Ba Sing Se. ♪
[laughing]
Nothing like a fat man
dancing for his dinner.
Here you go.
Such a kind man.
[warbles]
[suspenseful music]
♪♪
Hey, you taking us down
for a reason?
Aang, why
are we going down?
What?
I didn't even notice.
[Sokka]
Are you noticing now?
Is something wrong?
I know this is gonna
sound weird,
but I think the swamp
is...calling to me.
Is it telling you where we
can get something to eat?
[Aang]
No, I-I think it wants us
to land there.
No offense to the swamp,
but I don't see any
land there to land on.
I don't know.
Bumi said to learn earthbending,
I would have to wait and listen.
And now I'm actually
hearing the earth.
Do you want me
to ignore it?
[warbles]
Yes.
I don't know.
There's something ominous
about that place.
[warbles]
[roars]
See? Even Appa and Momo
don't like it here.
Okay, since everyone feels so
strongly about this, bye, swamp.
Yip, yip.
[rumbling]
[Sokka]
You better throw in
an extra yip.
We gotta move.
Ah!
[yelling]
[all]
Ah!
Ugh.
Where's Appa and Momo?
Appa!
Momo!
Sokka, you've got
an elbow leech.
Where, where?
Where do you think?
Why do things
keep attaching to me?
You couldn't
find them?
[Aang]
No.
And the tornado,
it just disappeared.
[growling]
[roars]
We better speed things up.
Maybe we should be a little
nicer to the swamp.
Aang, these are just plants.
Do you want me to say please
and thank you
as I swing my machete
back and forth?
Maybe you should listen
to Aang.
Something about this place
feels... alive.
I'm sure there are lots of
things that are alive here.
And if we don't want to wind
up getting eaten by them,
we need to find Appa
as fast as we can.
[supersonic whistle]
[roars]
[gurgles]
[Katara]
Appa!
Momo?
There's no way they can hear us
and no way we can see them.
We'll have to make camp
for the night.
Ah, ugh!
What was that?
Nothing, just swamp gas.
Look, there's nothing
supernatural going on here.
[all]
Eugh.
[human-like screams]
[screams]
I think we should
build a fire.
[blade chinking]
Sokka, the longer we're here,
the more I think you
shouldn't be doing that.
No, I asked the swamp.
It said this was fine.
Right, swamp?
[squeakily]
No problem, Sokka.
[blade chinks]
Does anyone else get the feeling
that we're being watched?
Please, we're all alone
out here.
[blade swooshing]
Except for them.
Right, except for them.
[frogs croaking]
[night sounds intensify]
[roars]
[night sounds stop]
[all yelp]
Hagh!
Ah!
[grunting]
Ugh!
Ugh.
Ah!
Guys?
What'd you reckon
make a track like that, Tho?
Don't know, Doo.
Something with six legs,
pretty big'uns, too.
[Doo]
Leaves a nice, wide trail
to follow.
You know what's at
the end of that trail?
Dinner.
[roars]
[growls]
[hisses]
[Katara]
Aang?
Sokka?
Hello?
Hello.
Can you help me?
Mom?
Mom!
I can't believe...
[gasps]
[sobbing]
Aang!
Stupid swamp.
Dumb, ugly vines.
Katara!
You think you're
so tough, huh?
[grunting]
Ah!
Hello?
Yue?
This is just a trick
of the light...
swamp gas.
I hit my head
running away last night.
I'm going crazy.
You didn't protect me.
[sighs]
Ah!
Katara!
Appa!
Hello?
Who are you?
[laughs]
Hey!
Come back.
[laughing]
[laughs]
Lookee there, Tho.
Is that a little hairy
fella riding that thing?
No, that's what
they call a "lemu."
Saw one at a traveling show
once--real smart, they say.
Bet he tastes a lot
like possum-chicken.
You think everything tastes
Come on, now, fellas,
just a little closer.
Nice and easy.
Nothin' to worry about.
We just fixin' to eat ya.
[growls]
What'd ya say that fer?
Well, we are.
But you don't have
to tell them that.
Well, how'd I know
they'd understand me?
Come on.
[laughing]
Who are you?
[both]
Ah!
Ugh.
[all]
What do you guys think
you're doing?
I've been looking
all over for you.
Well, I've been wandering
around looking for you.
I was chasing some girl.
What girl?
I don't know.
I heard laughing, and I saw
some girl in a fancy dress.
Well, there must be
a tea party here,
and we just didn't get
our invitations.
I thought I saw Mom.
Look, we were all
just scared and hungry,
and our minds were
playing tricks on us.
That's why we all
saw things out here.
You saw something, too?
I thought I saw Yue.
But that doesn't
prove anything.
Look, I think about
her all the time.
And you saw Mom,
someone you miss a lot.
What about me?
I didn't know
the girl I saw.
And all our visions
led us right here.
Okay, so where's here,
the middle of the swamp?
Yeah...
the center.
It's the heart
of the swamp.
It's been
calling us here.
I knew it.
It's just a tree.
It can't call anyone.
For the last time,
there's nothing after us,
and there's nothing
magical happening here.
[all]
Ah!
[yelling]
Ugh.
[grunting]
Ah!
Ugh!
Ugh.
Ah!
Ugh!
[grunting]
Ugh.
Now, what would a "lemu"
need a shirt fer?
Ah!
Ugh!
[growling]
[grunting]
[both]
Ugh!
Ah!
Ugh.
There's someone in there.
He's bending the vines.
Uh!
Ah!
Why did you call me here
if you just wanted to kill us?
Wait.
I didn't call you here.
We were flying over, and I heard
something calling to me,
telling me to land.
He's the Avatar.
Stuff like that
happens to us a lot.
The Avatar?
Come with me.
[Katara]
So who are you, then?
I protect the swamp from
folks that want to hurt it,
like this fellow
with his big knife.
See?
Completely reasonable--
not a monster,
just a regular guy
defending his home.
Nothing mystical about it.
[man]
Oh, the swamp
is a mystical place, all right.
It's sacred.
I reached enlightenment
right here under
the banyan grove tree.
I heard it calling me,
just like you did.
Sure you did.
It seems real chatty.
See, this whole swamp
is actually just one tree
spread out over miles.
Branches spread then sink
and take root
and then spread some more--
one big, living organism,
just like the entire world.
I get how the tree is one big
thing, but the whole world?
Sure.
You think you're any different
from me or your friends
or this tree?
If you listen hard enough,
you can hear every living thing
breathing together.
You can feel everything growing.
We are all living together even
if most folks don't act like it.
We all have the same roots,
and we are all branches
of the same tree.
[Katara]
But what did
our visions mean?
In the swamp, we see visions
of people we've lost,
people we loved,
folks we think are gone.
But the swamp tells us
they're not.
We're still connected to 'em.
Time is an illusion,
and so is death.
But what about my vision?
It was someone
I had never met.
You're the Avatar.
You tell me.
Time is an illusion,
so it's someone I will meet.
Sorry to interrupt
the lesson,
but we still need
to find Appa and Momo.
I think I know
how to find them.
Everything is connected.
Come on, we've gotta hurry.
♪ Set my lines
by the riverbed. ♪
♪ Caught ten fish,
and I killed 'em dead. ♪
♪ Cut 'em and gut 'em,
and I toss the heads ♪
♪ In the water to keep
them cat-gators fed. ♪
[all]
Ah!
Appa!
Oh!
We're under attack.
Hey, you guys
are Waterbenders.
You, too?
That means we're kin.
Hey, Huu.
How you been?
You know, scared some folks,
swung some vines--the usual.
Huu?
[twangy banjo-like music]
How you like
that possum-chicken?
Tastes just like
arctic hen.
So why were you guys
so interested in eating Appa?
You've get plenty of those
big things wandering around.
You want me to eat
ol' Slim?
He's like a member
of the family.
Nice Slim.
[growls]
Ah!
[laughing]
Oh, he don't eat no bugs.
That's people food.
Where'd you say
you was from?
The South Pole.
Didn't know there was
Waterbenders anywhere but here.
They got a nice
swamp there, do they?
No, it's all ice
and snow.
Mm, no wonder you left.
Well, I hope
you realize now
that nothing strange
was going on here--
just a bunch of greasy
people living in a swamp.
What about the visions?
I told you: we were hungry.
I'm eating a giant bug.
Mm-ugh.
But what about when
the tree showed me
where Appa and Momo were?
That's Avatar stuff.
That doesn't count.
The only thing
I can't figure out
is how you made the tornado
that sucked us down.
I can't do anything like that.
I just bend the water
in the plants.
Well, no accounting
for weather.
Still, there's absolutely
nothing mysterious
about the swamp.
[screaming]
thwack!
Who's there?
Whoa!
Ugh.
♪♪