WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
Girl: LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER
NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪♪
THIS IS HUMILIATING.
WE'RE ROYALTY.
THESE PEOPLE SHOULD BE
GIVING US WHATEVER WE WANT.
WHO'S THERE?
♪♪
THERE'S NO TIME
TO SAY GOODBYE.
[KISSES]
Aang: THIS ISLAND IS
NAMED FOR KYOSHI?
I KNOW KYOSHI.
AVATAR KYOSHI WAS BORN
HERE 400 YEARS AGO.
SHE'S BEEN DEAD
FOR CENTURIES.
♪♪
[SNORES]
[CHATTERS]
[BUZZES]
EH--
[SQUEALS]
PTH--TH--TH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MY MOUTH?
[PURRS]
MOMO, YOU NEED
TO BE A LITTLE
MORE SENSITIVE
TO MY BOUNDARIES.
AH!
HUH?
[GASPS]
GIVE UP.
YOU'RE COMPLETELY
SURROUNDED.
Man: COME ON!
COME ON, COME ON!
MY SCROLLS!
MY STAFF!
UH!
[GRUNTING]
YUP, YUP!
AAH!
WAIT,
MY BOOMERANG!
THERE'S NO TIME!
OH, I SEE.
SO THERE'S TIME
TO GET YOUR SCROLLS,
AND TIME
TO GET YOUR STAFF,
BUT NO TIME
FOR MY BOOMERANG?
THAT'S CORRECT.
OH.
SORRY ABOUT
YOUR BOOMERANG,
SOKKA.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE LOST
PART OF MY IDENTITY.
IMAGINE IF YOU
LOST YOUR ARROW,
OR IF KATARA
LOST HER...
HAIR LOOPIES.
HERE'S YOUR
PRODUCE,
PONY TAIL GUY.
I USED TO BE
BOOMERANG GUY.
HEY, WATER
TRIBE MONEY.
I HOPE
THAT'S OK.
SO LONG
AS IT'S MONEY.
HAVE A NICE
AVATAR DAY!
AVATAR DAY?
YOU GUYS ARE GOING
TO THE FESTIVAL,
RIGHT?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
THERE'S A HOLIDAY
FOR THE AVATAR.
WHO KNEW?
LOOK!
THEY MADE A GIANT
KYOSHI FLOAT.
Sokka: AND HERE COMES
AVATAR ROKU.
Aang: HAVING
A HUGE FESTIVAL
IN YOUR HONOR
IS GREAT, BUT FRANKLY,
IT'S JUST NICE
TO BE APPRECIATED.
AND IT'S NICE
TO APPRECIATE
THEIR DEEP-FRIED
FESTIVAL FOOD.
AANG, LOOK!
Aang: THAT'S THE BIGGEST
ME I'VE EVER SEEN.
THEY HAVE A TORCH.
THAT'S A NICE PROP.
IT'S BRIGHT,
DANGEROUS...
[SNIFFS]
SMELLS MANLY.
BUT I'M NOT SURE
I COULD CARRY IT OFF.
HEY, WHAT'S
THAT GUY DOING?
[YELLS]
Crowd: DOWN WITH
THE AVATAR!
DOWN WITH
Crowd:
DOWN WITH THE AVATAR!
UH! UH!
WHERE DID YOU
GET THESE?
WHAT DOES IT MATTER
WHERE THEY CAME FROM?
HMM.
MMM!
Crowd:
DOWN WITH THE AVATAR!
UH!
[CHEERS]
THAT
PARTY POOPER'S
RUINING
AVATAR DAY!
THAT
PARTY POOPER'S
MY FRIEND.
IT'S THE AVATAR
HIMSELF!
Man: IT'S GOING
TO KILL US
WITH ITS AWESOME
AVATAR POWERS!
NO,
I'M NOT, I--
AAH! AAH!
OH, HO, HO!
I SUGGEST
YOU LEAVE.
YOU'RE NOT
WELCOME HERE, AVATAR.
WHY NOT?
AANG HELPS
PEOPLE.
IT'S TRUE.
I'M ON YOUR SIDE.
I FIND THAT
HARD TO SWALLOW,
CONSIDERING WHAT
YOU DID TO US
IN YOUR PAST LIFE!
IT WAS AVATAR KYOSHI.
SHE MURDERED
OUR GLORIOUS LEADER,
CHIN THE GREAT.
YOU THINK THAT I...
MURDERED SOMEONE?
Man: WE USED TO BE
A GREAT SOCIETY
BEFORE YOU KILLED
OUR LEADER.
NOW LOOK AT US!
AH!
AANG WOULD NEVER DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
NO AVATAR WOULD.
AND IT'S NOT
FAIR FOR YOU ALL
TO QUESTION
HIS HONOR!
LET'S TELL HER
WHAT WE THINK
OF THE
AVATAR'S HONOR!
PFF!
[CHEERING]
Aang: GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO CLEAR MY NAME.
THE ONLY WAY
TO PROVE YOUR INNOCENCE
IS TO STAND TRIAL.
I'LL GLADLY
STAND TRIAL.
YOU'LL HAVE TO FOLLOW
ALL OUR RULES.
THAT INCLUDES
PAYING BAIL.
NO PROBLEM.
HOW WAS I
SUPPOSED TO KNOW
THEY WOULDN'T TAKE
WATER TRIBE MONEY?
Sokka:
SO SOME PEOPLE
DON'T LIKE YOU,
BIG DEAL.
THERE'S
A WHOLE NATION
OF FIREBENDERS
WHO HATE YOU.
NOW LET'S BUST YOU
OUT OF HERE.
I CAN'T.
SURE YOU CAN!
A LITTLE--
[BLOWS AIR]
SWISH, SWISH, SWISH!
AIRBENDING SLICE!
AND WE'RE ON
OUR WAY.
Katara: I THINK
WHAT MASTER SWISH
IS TRYING TO SAY,
IS THAT YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO BE OUT
SAVING THE WORLD.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT
LOCKED UP IN HERE.
I CAN'T DO THAT
WITH PEOPLE THINKING
I'M A MURDERER,
EITHER.
I NEED YOU GUYS TO HELP
PROVE MY INNOCENCE.
HOW ARE WE
GONNA DO THAT?
THE CRIME HAPPENED
OVER 300 YEARS AGO.
THAT'S OK, SOKKA.
FOR SOME REASON,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
AN EXPERT DETECTIVE.
WELL,
I GUESS I COULD
BE CLASSIFIED
AS SUCH.
YEAH! BACK HOME,
HE WAS FAMOUS FOR
SOLVING THE MYSTERY
OF THE MISSING
SEAL JERKY.
EVERYONE WANTED
TO BLAME IT ON
THE POLAR LEOPARD,
BUT I FIGURED OUT
IT WAS OLD MAN JARCO
WEARING
POLAR LEOPARD BOOTS.
SEE, A REAL 800 POUND
POLAR LEOPARD
WOULD'VE LEFT
MUCH DEEPER TRACKS.
OK, I GUESS
I AM PRETTY GOOD.
SO YOU'LL HELP ME
WITH MY CASE?
FINE.
BUT I'M GONNA NEED
SOME NEW PROPS.
I'M READY.
[LAUGHS]
WHAT?
[GRUNTING]
UH!
Man: AH!
WHEW.
EH--AH!
AAH!
OHH...
Mayor: THIS
IS THE CRIME SCENE.
THIS IS THE FOOTPRINT
OF THE KILLER, KYOSHI.
IT WAS AT SUNSET,
370 YEARS AGO
TODAY,
THAT SHE EMERGED
FROM THE TEMPLE
AND STRUCK DOWN
CHIN THE GREAT.
AFTER THAT
TRAGIC DAY,
WE BUILT
THIS STATUE
TO IMMORTALIZE
OUR GREAT LEADER.
FEEL FREE
TO APPRECIATE IT.
THIS TEMPLE
AND THIS STATUE
WERE CUT FROM
THE SAME STONE.
AND WE KNOW
THAT THE STATUE
WAS BUILT
AFTER CHIN DIED.
Katara: SO IF
THEY WERE BUILT
AT THE SAME TIME,
THAT MEANS--
SHH!
I WANNA
SOLVE IT!
THAT MEANS,
KYOSHI NEVER SET FOOT
IN THIS TEMPLE.
Katara: THAT'S A BIG HOLE
IN THE MAYOR'S STORY,
BUT IT'S NOT ENOUGH
TO PROVE
AANG'S INNOCENCE.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE NEED TO GO
TO KYOSHI ISLAND.
WHERE'D YOU
GET THAT?
[SNIFFING]
[SQUEAKS]
Man:
YOU GOT A BALD HEAD...
SOME NICE TATTOOS.
ARGH!
YOU'RE
GOING TO FIT IN
REAL WELL
AROUND HERE.
[BELL RINGS]
[LAUGHS]
[GRUNTING]
[CHEERING]
OHH!
WATA--
AH--DWA--
OH--AH--AAH!
WAH,
HO, HO, HO!
[SPUTTERS]
WHERE'S AANGY?
HE COULDN'T
BE HERE, KOKO.
OHH...
Koko: I WANT
TO SEE AANGY.
OH.
OYAJI,
AANG IS IN JAIL.
THE TOWN OF CHIN
SAYS HE MURDERED
THEIR LEADER
IN A PAST LIFE.
THEY SAY
IT WAS KYOSHI.
KYOSHI? THAT'S
CRAZY TALK.
I'LL TAKE YOU
TO HER SHRINE.
MAYBE
SOMETHING THERE
WILL HELP YOU
CLEAR HER NAME.
SO, UH...
WHAT'S SUKI
UP TO?
IS SHE AROUND?
ACTUALLY, SHE AND
THE OTHER WARRIORS
LEFT TO FIGHT
IN THE WAR.
YOU KIDS HAD
A BIG IMPACT ON SUKI.
SHE SAID
YOU INSPIRED HER,
AND SHE WANTED
TO HELP CHANGE THE WORLD.
OH, WELL...
THAT'S GREAT.
Oyaji: THIS TEMPLE
WAS CONVERTED INTO A SHRINE
TO KYOSHI.
THE CLERICS TELL US
THESE RELICS
ARE STILL CONNECTED
TO HER SPIRIT.
THAT'S HER KIMONO.
SHE HAD
EXQUISITE TASTE.
PLEASE
DON'T TOUCH!
Sokka:
THESE FANS,
THEY WERE HER
WEAPONS, NO?
ALSO REFRAIN
FROM TOUCHING THE FANS.
THESE WERE
HER BOOTS?
HER FEET MUST HAVE
BEEN ENORMOUS.
[SQUEAKS]
THE BIGGEST
OF ANY AVATAR.
WAIT A MINUTE,
BIG FEET?
LITTLE FOOTPRINTS?
THERE'S NO WAY!
[CLEARS THROAT]
SPECIAL OUTFIT,
HAT AND PIPE,
THESE THINGS MEAN
ANYTHING TO YOU?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
PLEASE.
AH, HAH!
THERE'S NO WAY
KYOSHI COULD HAVE
MADE THAT FOOTPRINT.
AND THEREFORE,
THERE IS NOTHING
LINKING HER TO
THE CRIME SCENE.
BRILLIANT,
SOKKA.
THIS GIRL YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT,
SHE'LL COME AROUND.
YOU JUST GOTTA
HANG IN THERE.
YOU THINK SO?
SURE.
YEAH.
YOU'RE A CATCH.
I DON'T KNOW.
HEY!
YOU'RE SMART,
HANDSOME, FUNNY,
NOT TO MENTION
YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT.
DON'T BE AFRAID
TO TELL HER
HOW YOU FEEL.
[SNIFFS]
THIS PIECE IS CALLED
"THE BIRTH OF KYOSHI."
IT WAS PAINTED
AT SUNRISE
ON THE DAY THIS
ISLAND WAS FOUNDED.
WHY, IT WAS TODAY,
IN FACT,
370 YEARS AGO.
[SPITS]
370 YEARS?
WAIT, ARE YOU SURE
IT WAS TODAY?
WELL, SEEING HOW
IT'S KYOSHI DAY,
YES, I'M SURE.
THIS CEREMONY DIDN'T
TAKE PLACE AT SUNRISE,
IT TOOK PLACE
AT SUNSET.
LOOK AT
THE SHADOWS.
THEY POINT EAST,
SO THE SUN MUST HAVE
BEEN IN THE WEST.
SO WHAT?
AAH!
IF KYOSHI WAS IN
THE CEREMONY AT SUNSET,
SHE COULDN'T
HAVE BEEN IN CHIN
COMMITTING THE CRIME.
SHE HAS AN ALIBI.
OH--UH!
Katara:
HONORABLE MAYOR,
WE'VE PREPARED
A SOLID DEFENSE
FOR THE AVATAR.
WE DID
AN INVESTIGATION,
AND FOUND SOME
VERY STRONG EVIDENCE.
Mayor:
EVIDENCE? HA!
THAT'S NOT HOW
OUR COURT SYSTEM WORKS.
THEN HOW CAN I
PROVE MY INNOCENCE?
SIMPLE.
I SAY WHAT HAPPENED,
AND THEN YOU SAY
WHAT HAPPENED,
AND THEN I DECIDE
WHO'S RIGHT.
[GASPS]
THAT'S WHY WE
CALL IT JUSTICE,
BECAUSE IT'S
JUST US.
[LAUGHING]
EVERYONE LOVED
CHIN THE GREAT,
BECAUSE HE WAS
SO GREAT.
THEN THE AVATAR
SHOWED UP
AND KILLED HIM,
AND THAT'S
HOW IT HAPPENED.
THE ACCUSED
WILL NOW
PRESENT
ITS ARGUMENT.
YOU CAN DO IT, AANG.
JUST REMEMBER
THE EVIDENCE.
RIGHT...
EVIDENCE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I'M ABOUT
TO TELL YOU
WHAT REALLY
HAPPENED,
AND I WILL PROVE IT
WITH FACTS.
FACT NUMBER ONE:
UH...
THE FOOTPRINTS.
OH, YEAH.
YOU SEE, I HAVE
VERY LARGE FEET.
FURTHERMORE,
YOUR TEMPLE...
MATCHES YOUR STATUE.
BUT I WAS IN
A PAINTING AT SUNSET.
SO THERE YOU HAVE IT.
I'M NOT GUILTY!
HE'S DEAD.
LOOKS LIKE YOU
DID SOME
SERIOUS SHOPPING.
BUT WHERE DID YOU
GET THE MONEY?
DO YOU LIKE
YOUR NEW TEAPOT?
TO BE HONEST
WITH YOU,
THE BEST TEA
TASTES DELICIOUS
WHETHER IT COMES
IN A PORCELAIN POT,
OR A TIN CUP.
I KNOW WE'VE HAD
SOME DIFFICULT
TIMES LATELY.
WE'VE HAD
TO STRUGGLE
JUST TO GET BY.
BUT IT'S NOTHING
TO BE ASHAMED OF.
THERE IS A SIMPLE
HONOR IN POVERTY.
THERE'S NO
HONOR FOR ME
WITHOUT
THE AVATAR.
ZUKO...
EVEN IF YOU DID
CAPTURE THE AVATAR,
I'M NOT SO SURE
IT WOULD SOLVE
OUR PROBLEMS.
NOT NOW.
THEN THERE IS
NO HOPE AT ALL.
NO, ZUKO!
YOU MUST NEVER
GIVE IN TO DESPAIR.
ALLOW YOURSELF
TO SLIP DOWN
THAT ROAD
AND YOU SURRENDER
TO YOUR LOWEST
INSTINCTS.
Uncle: IN THE
DARKEST TIMES,
HOPE IS SOMETHING
YOU GIVE YOURSELF.
THAT IS THE MEANING
OF INNER STRENGTH.
Katara: MAYOR TOM.
I'D LIKE FOR
THE COURT TO HEAR
ONE LAST TESTIMONY.
I'VE ALREADY
TOLD YOU!
IT'S JUST ME
AND THE ACCUSED.
YOU CAN'T CALL
ANY WITNESSES.
THIS ISN'T
JUST ANY WITNESS.
I'M GOING
TO CALL...
AVATAR KYOSHI
HERSELF!
[WHISPERING]
ARE THEY SERIOUS?
Man:
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
WELL, SHE IS
AANG'S PAST LIFE.
MAYBE WEARING
HER STUFF
WILL TRIGGER
SOMETHING.
I DO BELIEVE IN
THE POWER OF STUFF.
THIS IS A MOCKERY
OF CHIN LAW!
PLEASE, IF YOU
COULD JUST WAIT
ONE MORE SECOND!
I'M SURE KYOSHI
WILL BE HERE.
HEY, EVERYBODY.
AVATAR KYOSHI HERE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
FOR THE MURDER
OF CHIN THE GREAT,
THIS COURT FINDS
THE AVATAR...
I KILLED
CHIN THE CONQUEROR...
A HORRIBLE TYRANT.
CHIN WAS EXPANDING
HIS ARMY
TO ALL CORNERS
OF THE CONTINENT.
WHEN THEY CAME
TO THE NECK
OF THE PENINSULA
WHERE WE LIVED,
HE DEMANDED OUR
IMMEDIATE SURRENDER.
I WARNED HIM
THAT I WOULD NOT
SIT PASSIVELY WHILE
HE TOOK OUR HOME.
BUT HE DID NOT
BACK DOWN.
ON THAT DAY,
WE SPLIT FROM THE MAINLAND.
♪♪
AAH!
[SPLASH]
Kyoshi: I CREATED
KYOSHI ISLAND
SO MY PEOPLE COULD BE SAFE
FROM INVADERS.
OHH...
SO...WHAT
JUST HAPPENED?
UH...YOU KIND OF
CONFESSED.
SORRY.
AND I FIND YOU
GUILTY!
BRING OUT THE WHEEL
OF PUNISHMENT!
[CHEERING]
[CHATTERS]
UNCLE...
I THOUGHT A LOT
ABOUT WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU DID?
GOOD, GOOD.
IT'S HELPED ME
REALIZE SOMETHING.
WE NO LONGER HAVE
ANYTHING TO GAIN
BY TRAVELING
TOGETHER.
I NEED TO FIND
MY OWN WAY.
Uncle: WAIT!
[GRUNTS]
Man: THE ACCUSED
WILL NOW
SPIN THE WHEEL
OF PUNISHMENT
TO DETERMINE
HIS SENTENCE.
I SAID I WOULD
FACE JUSTICE,
SO I WILL.
COME ON
TORTURE MACHINE!
EATEN BY BEARS!
RAZOR PIT!
COMMUNITY SERVICE!
PLEASE STOP ON
Man: LOOKS LIKE
IT'S BOILED IN OIL.
[CHEERING]
Man: WE'VE COME TO CLAIM
THIS VILLAGE
FOR THE FIRE LORD!
NOW SHOW ME YOUR LEADER,
SO I MAY...
DETHRONE HIM.
THAT'S HIM
OVER THERE!
AAH!
YOU, AVATAR.
DO SOMETHING!
GEE, I'D LOVE
TO HELP,
BUT I'M SUPPOSED
TO BE BOILED IN OIL.
THERE,
COMMUNITY SERVICE.
NOW SERVE OUR
COMMUNITY
AND GET RID
OF THOSE RHINOS!
[GROWLS]
UH!
[SPLASH]
[GROWLS]
AAH!
ROUGH RHINOS,
TO THE TOWN!
[SCREAMING]
AAH!
[GASPS]
BOOMERANG!
YOU DO ALWAYS
COME BACK.
AH!
UH!
Mayor: FROM NOW ON,
WE'LL CELEBRATE
A NEW AVATAR DAY,
IN HONOR OF THE DAY
AVATAR AANG
SAVED US FROM
THE ROUGH RHINO INVASION.
WHAT
IS THIS?
Mayor: THAT'S OUR NEW
FESTIVAL FOOD.
UNFRIED DOUGH.
MAY WE EAT IT
AND BE REMINDED
OF HOW ON THIS DAY
THE AVATAR WAS NOT
BOILED IN OIL.
[CHEERING]
HAPPY AVATAR DAY,
EVERYONE.
THIS IS BY FAR
THE WORST TOWN
WE'VE EVER BEEN TO.
♪♪