Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
Katara: WE NEED
TO FIND KING BUMI
SO AANG CAN LEARN
EARTHBENDING
SOMEWHERE SAFE.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE
HEADED TO OMASHU.
I PRESENT TO YOU
THE EARTH KINGDOM CITY
OF O--OH, NO.
I GUESS I NEED TO
FIND SOMEONE ELSE
TO TEACH ME
EARTHBENDING.
YOU NEED TO FIND SOMEONE
WHO WAITS AND LISTENS
BEFORE STRIKING.
IN THE SWAMP, WE SEE
VISIONS OF PEOPLE
WE'VE LOST,
PEOPLE WE LOVED.
BUT WHAT ABOUT MY VISION?
IT WAS SOMEONE
I HAD NEVER MET.
IT'S PRICEY,
BUT I REALLY
DO LIKE IT.
THEN YOU SHOULD GET IT.
YOU DESERVE SOMETHING NICE.
I DO, DON'T I?
BUT NO. IT'S
TOO EXPENSIVE.
I SHOULDN'T.
ALL RIGHT. THEN DON'T.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA GET IT.
PSST, PSST.
HEY, YOU
KIDS LIKE
EARTHBENDING?
YOU LIKE
THROWING ROCKS?
THEN CHECK OUT
MASTER YU'S
EARTHBENDING
ACADEMY.
Aang: LOOK. THERE'S
A COUPON ON THE BACK.
THE FIRST LESSON IS FREE.
WHO KNOWS? THIS
MASTER YU COULD BE
THE EARTHBENDING
TEACHER YOU'VE BEEN
LOOKING FOR.
[SNIFFS]
TAKE YOUR STANCES.
NOW STRIKE AS IF YOU'RE PUNCHING
THROUGH YOUR OPPONENT'S HEAD.
HYAH!
SO ARE YOU READY TO COMMIT
TO MORE LESSONS?
IF YOU PAY FOR THE WHOLE YEAR
IN ADVANCE,
I'LL BUMP YOU UP
TO THE NEXT BELT.
HE'S NOT THE ONE.
I THINK THE BOULDER
IS GONNA WIN
BACK THE BELT
AT EARTH
RUMBLE 6.
HE'S GONNA HAVE
TO FIGHT HIS WAY THROUGH
THE BEST EARTHBENDERS
IN THE WORLD TO EVEN
GET A SHOT AT THE CHAMP.
EXCUSE ME.
BUT WHERE IS
THIS EARTHBENDING
TOURNAMENT EXACTLY?
IT'S ON THE ISLAND
OF NONEOYA--
NONE O' YA BUSINESS.
HA HA!
OH, I GOT TO
REMEMBER THAT ONE.
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF THIS.
HEY, STRONG GUYS,
WAIT UP.
WHAT WAS I THINKING?
I DON'T NEED A NEW BAG.
WHY'D YOU LET
ME BUY THIS?
[PURRING]
YOU READY TO FIND
AN EARTHBENDING
TEACHER,
BECAUSE WE'RE GOING
TO EARTH RUMBLE 6.
HOW DID YOU GET THEM
TO TELL YOU?
OH, A GIRL HAS HER WAYS.
[CROWD CHEERING]
HEY, FRONT ROW SEATS.
I WONDER WHY NO ONE
ELSE IS SITTING HERE.
I GUESS THAT'S WHY.
[CHEERING GROWS LOUDER]
WELCOME TO EARTH RUMBLE 6.
I AM YOUR HOST, XIN FU.
THIS IS JUST
GONNA BE A BUNCH
OF GUYS
CHUCKING ROCKS
AT EACH OTHER,
ISN'T IT?
THAT'S WHAT I PAID FOR.
THE RULES ARE SIMPLE.
JUST KNOCK THE OTHER GUY
OUT OF THE RING,
AND YOU WIN.
[BELL RINGS]
ROUND ONE--THE BOULDER
VERSUS THE BIG BAD HIPPO!
[YELLS]
LISTEN UP, HIPPO.
YOU MAY BE BIG,
BUT YOU AIN'T BAD.
THE BOULDER'S GONNA
WIN THIS IN A LANDSLIDE.
HIPPO MAD!
HYAH!
Xin Fu: UNBELIEVABLE,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THE HIPPO IS ROCKING
THE BOULDER.
THE BOULDER WINS.
[CROWD CHEERS]
HOW ABOUT
THE BOULDER?
HE'S GOT
SOME GOOD MOVES.
I DON'T KNOW.
BUMI SAID I NEED A TEACHER
WHO LISTENS TO THE EARTH.
HE'S JUST LISTENING
TO HIS BIG MUSCLES.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
SOKKA?
HA HA! WHOO!
NEXT MATCH, THE BOULDER
VERSUS FIRE NATION MAN.
[CROWD BOOS]
BOO! BOO!
PLEASE DO RISE
FOR FIRE NATION
NATIONAL ANTHEM.
♪ FIRE LORD, MY FLAME
BURNS FOR THEE ♪
[CROWD BOOING]
GO BACK
TO THE FIRE NATION.
NO. NO, PLEASE!
AAH!
YEAH! WHOO!
THE BOULDER KNOWS HOW
TO PUT THE HURT
IN THE DIRT.
YEAH! WHOO!
[ORGAN PLAYING]
[BELL RINGS]
NOW THE MOMENT YOU'VE
ALL BEEN WAITING FOR--
THE BOULDER VERSUS YOUR
CHAMPION--THE BLIND BANDIT.
[CROWD CHEERS]
[CROWD CHANTING "BANDIT"]
SHE CAN'T REALLY
BE BLIND.
IT'S JUST
PART OF HER
CHARACTER, RIGHT?
I THINK SHE IS.
I THINK SHE IS...
GOING DOWN!
THE BOULDER
FEELS CONFLICTED
ABOUT FIGHTING
A YOUNG BLIND GIRL.
SOUNDS TO ME LIKE
YOU'RE SCARED, BOULDER.
THE BOULDER'S OVER
HIS CONFLICTED
FEELINGS,
AND NOW HE'S READY
TO BURY YOU IN
A ROCK-ALANCHE.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY,
THE PEBBLE.
HA HA HA!
[GIGGLES]
IT'S ON.
[GROWLING]
[GROWLING IN
SLOW MOTION]
WHOA!
OOH.
OOH!
Xin Fu: YOUR WINNER,
AND STILL THE CHAMPION,
THE BLIND BANDIT.
[CRYING]
NO!
HOW DID SHE
DO THAT?
SHE WAITED AND LISTENED.
TO MAKE THINGS A LITTLE
MORE INTERESTING,
I'M OFFERING UP
THIS SACK OF GOLD PIECES
TO ANYONE WHO CAN DEFEAT
THE BLIND BANDIT.
WHAT? NO ONE DARES
TO FACE HER?
I WILL.
GO, AANG!
AVENGE THE BOULDER!
DO PEOPLE REALLY
WANT TO SEE TWO
LITTLE GIRLS
FIGHTING OUT HERE?
Crowd: OOH.
I DON'T REALLY
WANT TO FIGHT YOU.
I WANT TO TALK
TO YOU.
BOO! NO TALKING!
DON'T BOO AT HIM.
SOMEBODY'S A LITTLE
LIGHT ON HIS FEET.
WHAT'S YOUR FIGHTING
NAME, THE FANCY DANCER?
WHERE'D YOU GO?
PLEASE, WAIT.
THERE YOU ARE.
AAH!
[CROWD CHEERS]
PLEASE LISTEN!
I NEED
AN EARTHBENDING
TEACHER,
AND I THINK IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE YOU.
WHOEVER YOU ARE,
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE.
WAIT!
[FANFARE]
Sokka: WAY TO GO, CHAMP.
I GOT TO ADMIT,
NOW I'M REALLY GLAD
I BOUGHT THIS BAG.
IT MATCHES THE BELT PERFECTLY.
THAT IS
A BIG RELIEF.
IF WE WANT TO FIND
THE BLIND BANDIT,
THE EARTHBENDING
ACADEMY IS A GOOD
PLACE TO START.
OH, GREAT. YOU AGAIN.
AAH!
YEAH. I DIDN'T THINK SO.
NICELY DONE.
HEY, YOU'RE THE KID
WHO BEAT THE BLIND BANDIT.
Aang: WE NEED
TO TALK TO HER.
DO YOU GUYS KNOW
WHERE SHE LIVES?
THE BLIND BANDIT'S
A MYSTERY.
SHE SHOWS UP TO FIGHT,
THEN DISAPPEARS.
LET ME
HANDLE THIS.
YOU'RE NOT TELLING
US EVERYTHING.
NO, NO. I SWEAR
IT'S TRUE.
NO ONE KNOWS
WHERE SHE GOES
OR WHO SHE REALLY IS.
THAT'S BECAUSE WE'RE ASKING
ABOUT THE WRONG PERSON.
IN MY VISION, I SAW A GIRL
IN A WHITE DRESS
WITH A PET FLYING BOAR.
KNOW ANYBODY LIKE THAT?
WELL, A FLYING BOAR
IS THE SYMBOL OF
THE BEI FONG FAMILY.
THEY'RE THE RICHEST
PEOPLE IN TOWN,
PROBABLY
THE WHOLE WORLD.
YEAH, BUT THEY DON'T
HAVE A DAUGHTER.
A FLYING BOAR
IS GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
YEAH. YOU
BETTER LEAVE.
HEY. I GOT
MY EYE ON YOU.
WATER TRIBE.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THE BOULDER WAS
STANDING RIGHT THERE.
I SAW THE KID STRIKE,
BUT THERE WAS
NO EARTHBENDING.
NOTHING MADE CONTACT.
THE BLIND BANDIT JUST
FELL OUT OF THE RING.
SHE MUST HAVE TOOK
A DIVE
AND SPLIT THE MONEY
WITH THE KID.
[YELLS]
NOBODY CHEATS XIN FU.
THAT'S THE FLYING BOAR
FROM MY VISION. COME ON.
[KIDS SCREAMING]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE,
TWINKLE TOES?
HOW DID YOU KNOW
IT WAS ME?
DON'T ANSWER TO
TWINKLE TOES.
IT'S NOT MANLY.
YOU'RE THE ONE
WHOSE BAG MATCHES
HIS BELT.
HOW DID YOU FIND ME?
WELL, A CRAZY
KING TOLD ME
I HAD TO FIND
THE EARTHBENDER
WHO LISTENS
TO THE EARTH.
AND THEN I
HAD A VISION IN
A MAGIC SWAMP, AND--
WHAT AANG IS
TRYING TO SAY
IS HE'S THE AVATAR,
AND IF HE DOESN'T MASTER
EARTHBENDING SOON,
HE WON'T BE ABLE
TO DEFEAT THE FIRE LORD.
NOT MY PROBLEM.
NOW GET OUT OF HERE
OR I'LL CALL THE GUARDS.
Sokka: LOOK, WE ALL
HAVE TO DO OUR PART
TO WIN THIS WAR.
AND YOURS IS TO TEACH
AANG EARTHBENDING.
GUARDS! GUARDS, HELP!
TOPH, WHAT HAPPENED?
I THOUGHT I HEARD
SOMEONE. I GOT SCARED.
YOU KNOW YOUR FATHER
DOESN'T WANT YOU
WANDERING THE GROUNDS
WITHOUT
SUPERVISION, TOPH.
[SNIFFS]
I'M PLEASED TO HEAR
THAT TOPH'S PRIVATE
LESSONS ARE GOING WELL,
BUT I WANT TO BE SURE
SHE'S NOT TRYING ANYTHING
TOO DANGEROUS.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
I'M KEEPING HER
AT THE BEGINNER'S
LEVEL--
BASIC FORMS
AND BREATHING
EXERCISES ONLY.
VERY GOOD.
EXCUSE ME, SIR,
BUT YOU HAVE A VISITOR.
WHO THINKS THEY ARE
SO IMPORTANT
THEY CAN JUST COME
TO MY HOME UNANNOUNCED?
UH, THE AVATAR, SIR.
[CHOMPING NOISILY]
BLOW ON IT.
IT'S TOO HOT FOR HER.
ALLOW ME.
OH, MY.
AVATAR AANG,
IT'S AN HONOR
TO HAVE YOU VISIT US.
IN YOUR OPINION,
HOW MUCH LONGER DO YOU
THINK THE WAR WILL LAST?
I'D LIKE TO DEFEAT
THE FIRE LORD BY
THE END OF SUMMER,
BUT I CAN'T DO THAT
WITHOUT FINDING
AN EARTHBENDING
TEACHER FIRST.
WELL, MASTER YU IS
THE FINEST TEACHER
IN THE LAND.
HE'S BEEN TEACHING TOPH
SINCE SHE WAS LITTLE.
THEN SHE MUST BE
A GREAT EARTHBENDER,
PROBABLY GOOD
ENOUGH TO TEACH
SOMEONE ELSE. OW!
TOPH IS STILL
LEARNING THE BASICS.
YES. AND, SADLY,
BECAUSE OF HER
BLINDNESS,
I DON'T THINK
SHE WILL EVER BECOME
A TRUE MASTER.
OH, I'M SURE SHE'S BETTER
THAN YOU THINK SHE IS.
UH!
[AH-CHOO]
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM?
WHAT'S
YOUR PROBLEM?
WELL,
SHALL WE MOVE
TO THE LIVING ROOM
FOR DESSERT, THEN?
GOOD NIGHT, BUDDY.
HYAH!
RELAX. LOOK, I'M
SORRY ABOUT DINNER.
LET'S CALL IT
A TRUCE, OK?
EVEN THOUGH I WAS
BORN BLIND, I'VE NEVER
HAD A PROBLEM SEEING.
I SEE WITH EARTHBENDING.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
SEEING WITH MY FEET.
I FEEL THE VIBRATIONS
IN THE EARTH,
AND I CAN SEE
WHERE EVERYTHING IS--
YOU, THAT TREE,
EVEN THOSE ANTS.
THAT'S AMAZING.
MY PARENTS
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THEY'VE ALWAYS
TREATED ME LIKE
I WAS HELPLESS.
IS THAT WHY YOU BECAME
THE BLIND BANDIT?
YEAH.
THEN WHY STAY HERE
WHERE YOU'RE NOT HAPPY?
THEY'RE MY PARENTS.
WHERE ELSE AM I
SUPPOSED TO GO?
YOU COULD COME WITH US.
YEAH. YOU GUYS
GET TO GO WHEREVER
YOU WANT.
NO ONE TELLING YOU
WHAT TO DO--
THAT'S THE LIFE.
IT'S JUST NOT
MY LIFE.
WE'RE BEING AMBUSHED.
I THINK YOU KIDS
OWE ME SOME MONEY.
WHOEVER TOOK AANG
AND TOPH LEFT THIS.
"IF YOU WANT TO SEE
YOUR DAUGHTER AGAIN,
BRING 500
GOLD PIECES
TO THE ARENA."
IT'S SIGNED "XIN FU
AND THE BOULDER."
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I HAVE THE BOULDER'S
AUTOGRAPH!
MASTER YU,
I NEED YOU
TO HELP ME
GET MY DAUGHTER
BACK.
WE'RE GOING WITH YOU.
POOR TOPH!
SHE MUST BE SO SCARED.
YOU THINK YOU'RE SO TOUGH,
WHY DON'T YOU COME UP HERE
SO I CAN SMACK THAT
GRIN OFF YOUR FACE?
I'M NOT SMILING.
Sokka: TOPH!
HERE'S YOUR MONEY.
NOW, LET THEM GO.
WHAT ABOUT AANG?
I THINK THE FIRE NATION
WILL PAY A HEFTY PRICE
FOR THE AVATAR.
NOW GET OUT OF MY RING.
GO. I'LL BE OK.
TOPH, THERE'S TOO MANY OF THEM.
WE NEED AN EARTHBENDER.
WE NEED YOU.
MY DAUGHTER
IS BLIND.
SHE IS BLIND
AND TINY
AND HELPLESS
AND FRAGILE.
SHE CANNOT
HELP YOU.
YES, I CAN.
LET HIM GO.
I BEAT YOU ALL BEFORE,
AND I'LL DO IT AGAIN.
THE BOULDER TAKES
ISSUE WITH THAT COMMENT.
WAIT.
THEY'RE MINE.
UGH.
HIT IT HARDER!
I'M TRYING.
AAH!
[GROWLING]
[EARTHBENDER YELLS]
I NEVER KNEW.
YOUR DAUGHTER'S
AMAZING.
[CRACK CRACK]
SHE'S THE GREATEST
EARTHBENDER
I'VE EVER SEEN.
DAD, I KNOW
IT'S PROBABLY HARD
FOR YOU
TO SEE ME THIS WAY,
BUT THE OBEDIENT LITTLE
HELPLESS BLIND GIRL
THAT YOU THINK I AM
JUST ISN'T ME.
I LOVE FIGHTING.
I LOVE BEING AN EARTHBENDER.
AND I'M REALLY, REALLY
GOOD AT IT.
I KNOW I'VE KEPT MY LIFE
SECRET FROM YOU,
BUT YOU WERE KEEPING ME SECRET
FROM THE WHOLE WORLD.
YOU WERE DOING IT
TO PROTECT ME.
BUT I'M 12 YEARS OLD, AND I'VE
NEVER HAD A REAL FRIEND.
SO NOW THAT YOU SEE
WHO I REALLY AM,
I HOPE IT DOESN'T CHANGE
THE WAY YOU FEEL ABOUT ME.
OF COURSE IT
DOESN'T CHANGE THE WAY
I FEEL ABOUT YOU, TOPH.
IT'S MADE ME
REALIZE SOMETHING.
IT HAS?
YES. I'VE LET YOU
HAVE FAR TOO MUCH
FREEDOM.
FROM NOW ON, YOU
WILL BE CARED FOR
AND GUARDED
24 HOURS A DAY.
BUT, DAD--
Mom: WE ARE DOING
THIS FOR YOUR
OWN GOOD, TOPH.
Mr. Bei Fong: PLEASE
ESCORT THE AVATAR
AND HIS FRIENDS OUT.
THEY ARE NO LONGER
WELCOME HERE.
I'M SORRY, TOPH.
I'M SORRY, TOO.
GOOD-BYE, AANG.
DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL FIND YOU
A TEACHER.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF AMAZING
EARTHBENDERS
OUT THERE.
NOT LIKE HER.
[DISTANT PANTING]
TOPH, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING HERE?
MY DAD CHANGED
HIS MIND.
HE SAID I WAS
FREE TO TRAVEL
THE WORLD.
WELL, WE'D BETTER
GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE YOUR DAD
CHANGES HIS MIND
AGAIN.
GOOD IDEA.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
A GREAT TEACHER, TOPH.
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
I WANT TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING.
OK.
AAH!
NOW WE'RE EVEN.
UM, I'LL TAKE
THE BELT BACK.
OW!
Sokka: SORRY.
Mr. Bei Fong: I KNOW YOU TWO
ARE VERY DIFFERENT,
BUT I BELIEVE YOU HAVE
A COMMON INTEREST.
THE AVATAR HAS KIDNAPPED
MY DAUGHTER.
I WANT YOU TO DO WHATEVER
IT TAKES TO BRING HER HOME.
♪♪