Girl: WATER, EARTH, FIRE, AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM. BUT
WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST...
HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I DISCOVERED
THE NEW AVATAR.
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
PLEASE, FATHER, I ONLY HAD
THE FIRE NATION'S
BEST INTERESTS AT HEART.
Man: YOU WILL LEARN RESPECT.
AND SUFFERING WILL BE
YOUR TEACHER.
WE NO LONGER HAVE ANYTHING
TO GAIN BY TRAVELING TOGETHER.
I NEED TO FIND MY OWN WAY.
YOU'RE LIKE MY SISTER.
MY FATHER SAYS SHE WAS
BORN LUCKY.
HE SAYS I WAS LUCKY TO BE BORN.
I DON'T NEED LUCK, THOUGH.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD TO
STRUGGLE AND FIGHT,
AND THAT'S MADE ME STRONG.
IT'S MADE ME WHO I AM.
♪
[ANIMAL GRUNTS]
[SNIFFS]
[STOMACH RUMBLES]
[ANIMAL GRUNTS]
[SIGHS]
[GASPS]
Man: COME ON, SPIDER-SNAKE EYES.
[LAUGHS]
YEAH!
[GRUNTS]
[ANIMAL GRUNTS]
COULD I GET SOME WATER,
A BAG OF FEED, AND SOMETHING
HOT TO EAT?
Man: NOT ENOUGH HERE
FOR A HOT MEAL.
I CAN GET YOU TWO BAGS OF FEED.
[LAUGHING]
OW!
Man: HEY!
YOU THROWING EGGS
AT US, STRANGER?
NO.
YOU SEE WHO DID THROW IT?
THAT YOUR FAVORITE WORD, "NO"?
EGG HAD TO COME FROM SOMEWHERE.
MAYBE A CHICKEN FLEW OVER.
[LAUGHS]
THANKS FOR YOUR CONTRIBUTION.
THE ARMY APPRECIATES
YOUR SUPPORT.
YOU BETTER LEAVE TOWN.
PENALTY FOR STAYING'S
A LOT STEEPER THAN
YOU CAN AFFORD, STRANGER.
TRUST ME.
Shopkeeper: THOSE SOLDIERS
ARE SUPPOSED TO PROTECT US
FROM THE FIRE NATION.
BUT THEY'RE JUST
A BUNCH OF THUGS.
THANKS FOR NOT RATTING ME OUT.
Boy: I'LL TAKE YOU TO MY HOUSE
AND FEED YOUR OSTRICH HORSE
FOR YOU.
COME ON, I OWE YOU.
[STOMACH GROWLS]
[OINKING]
NO ONE CAN EVER SNEAK UP ON US.
TUH, NO KIDDING.
[PIG-ROOSTER CROWS]
YOU A FRIEND OF LEE'S?
THIS GUY JUST STOOD UP TO
THE SOLDIERS.
BY THE END, HE PRACTICALLY
HAD THEM RUNNING AWAY.
DOES THIS GUY HAVE A NAME?
I'M, UH...
Man: HE DOESN'T HAVE TO
SAY WHO HE IS IF HE
DOESN'T WANT TO, SELA.
ANYONE WHO CAN HOLD HIS OWN
AGAINST THOSE BULLY SOLDIERS
IS WELCOME HERE.
THOSE MEN SHOULD BE ASHAMED
TO WEAR EARTH KINGDOM UNIFORMS.
THE REAL SOLDIERS ARE OFF
FIGHTING THE WAR.
LIKE LEE'S BIG BROTHER, SEN SU.
SUPPER'S GOING TO BE READY SOON.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO STAY?
Zuko: I CAN'T.
I SHOULD BE MOVING ON.
GANSU COULD USE SOME HELP
ON THE BARN.
WHY DON'T YOU TWO WORK FOR
A WHILE, AND THEN WE'LL EAT?
YOU DON'T SEEM LIKE
YOU'RE FROM AROUND HERE.
MM-MM.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM, THEN?
FAR AWAY.
OH...
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
LEE, GIVE IT A REST.
STOP ASKING THE MAN
PERSONAL QUESTIONS, GOT IT?
[SIGHS]
YES.
SO HOW'D YOU GET THAT SCAR?
[GRUNTS]
IT'S NOT NICE TO BOTHER PEOPLE
ABOUT THINGS THEY MIGHT NOT
WANT TO TALK ABOUT.
THE MAN'S PAST IS HIS BUSINESS.
[BIRDS SINGING]
HEY, MOM, WANT TO SEE HOW AZULA
FEEDS TURTLE DUCKS?
ZUKO, WHY WOULD YOU DO THAT?
[QUACKS]
OW, OW-OW!
OW!
[QUACKING]
STUPID TURTLE DUCK.
WHY'D SHE DO THAT?
ZUKO, THAT'S WHAT MOMS ARE LIKE.
IF YOU MESS WITH
THEIR BABIES, HRUM!
THEY'RE GONNA BITE YOU BACK.
[ZUKO LAUGHS]
[AZULA GRUNTS]
[AZULA LAUGHS]
Girl: AZULA!
WATCH THIS.
MOM, CAN YOU MAKE ZUKO
PLAY WITH US?
WE NEED EQUAL TEAMS
TO PLAY A GAME.
I AM NOT CARTWHEELING.
YOU WON'T HAVE TO,
CARTWHEELING'S NOT A GAME,
DUMB-DUMB.
I DON'T CARE,
I DON'T WANT TO PLAY WITH YOU.
WE ARE BROTHER AND SISTER.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US
TO SPEND TIME TOGETHER.
DON'T YOU THINK SO, MOM?
YES, DARLING, I THINK IT'S
A GOOD IDEA TO PLAY WITH
YOUR SISTER.
GO ON, NOW, JUST FOR
A LITTLE WHILE.
Azula: HERE'S THE WAY IT GOES.
NOW WHAT YOU DO IS TRY TO
KNOCK THE APPLE OFF THE OTHER
PERSON'S HEAD, LIKE THIS.
[SCREAMS]
[AZULA LAUGHS]
SEE, I TOLD YOU IT WOULD WORK.
Girl: AW, THEY'RE SO CUTE
TOGETHER.
YOU TWO ARE SUCH, UGH.
I WAS JUST COMING TO GET YOU.
UNCLE IROH SENT US A LETTER
FROM THE WAR FRONT.
YOU'RE SOAKING WET.
Zuko: GIRLS ARE CRAZY!
Iroh: "IF THE CITY IS AS
MAGNIFICENT AS ITS WALL
BA SING SE MUST BE SOMETHING
TO BEHOLD.
I HOPE YOU ALL
MAY SEE IT SOME DAY.
IF WE DON'T BURN IT
TO THE GROUND, FIRST."
[LAUGHS]
"UNTIL THEN, ENJOY THESE GIFTS."
"FOR ZUKO, A PEARL DAGGER
FROM THE GENERAL WHO SURRENDERED
WHEN WE BROKE THROUGH
THE OUTER WALL.
NOTE THE INSCRIPTION AND
THE SUPERIOR CRAFTSMANSHIP."
"NEVER GIVE UP WITHOUT A FIGHT."
Mother: "AND FOR AZULA.
A NEW FRIEND.
SHE WEARS THE LATEST FASHION
FOR EARTH KINGDOM GIRLS."
IF UNCLE DOESN'T
MAKE IT BACK FROM WAR
THEN DAD WOULD BE NEXT IN LINE
TO BE FIRE LORD, WOULDN'T HE?
AZULA, WE DON'T SPEAK THAT WAY.
IT WOULD BE AWFUL IF UNCLE IROH
DIDN'T RETURN.
AND BESIDES, FIRE LORD AZULON IS
A PICTURE OF HEALTH.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE IT IF COUSIN
LU TEN WANTED DAD TO DIE?
I STILL THINK OUR DAD WOULD MAKE
A MUCH BETTER FIRE LORD THAN
HIS ROYAL TEA-LOVING KOOKY-NESS.
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
[LEE GRUNTS]
Zuko: YOU'RE HOLDING THEM
ALL WRONG.
[LEE SCREAMS]
KEEP IN MIND,
THESE ARE DUAL SWORDS.
TWO HALVES OF A SINGLE WEAPON.
DON'T THINK OF THEM AS SEPARATE,
BECAUSE THEY'RE NOT.
THEY'RE JUST TWO DIFFERENT PARTS
OF THE SAME WHOLE.
[LEE GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
Lee: I THINK YOU'D REALLY LIKE
MY BROTHER, SEN SU.
HE USED TO SHOW ME STUFF
LIKE THIS ALL THE TIME.
[OINKING]
Sela: HERE, THIS OUGHT TO
GET YOU THROUGH A FEW MEALS.
[HOOVES BEATING THE GROUND]
WHAT DO YOU THINK THEY WANT?
TROUBLE.
[OSTRICH HORSES GRUNTING]
[OINKING AND SQUEALING]
Gansu: WHAT DO YOU WANT, GOW?
JUST THOUGHT SOMEONE OUGHT TO
TELL YOU YOUR SON'S BATTALION
GOT CAPTURED.
YOU BOYS HEAR WHAT
THE FIRE NATION DID WITH
THEIR LAST GROUP OF
EARTH KINGDOM PRISONERS?
DRESSED 'EM UP IN FIRE NATION
UNIFORMS AND PUT THEM ON
THE FRONT LINE UNARMED,
WAY I HEARD IT.
THEN THEY JUST WATCHED.
YOU WATCH YOUR MOUTH.
[OSTRICH HORSE GRUNTS]
WHY BOTHER ROOTING AROUND
IN THE MUD WITH THESE PIGS?
[OSTRICH HORSES GRUNT]
[LAUGHTER]
IROH HAS LOST HIS SON.
YOUR COUSIN, LU TEN,
DID NOT SURVIVE THE BATTLE.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
TO MY BROTHER?
Gansu: I'M GOING TO THE FRONT.
I'M GOING TO FIND SEN SU
AND BRING HIM BACK.
[SELA CRIES]
Lee: WHEN MY DAD GOES
WILL YOU STAY?
NO.
I NEED TO MOVE ON.
HERE, I WANT YOU TO HAVE THIS.
READ THE INSCRIPTION.
"MADE IN EARTH KINGDOM."
THE OTHER ONE.
"NEVER GIVE UP WITHOUT A FIGHT."
[OSTRICH HORSE GRUNTS]
[OINKING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
YOU WASTE ALL YOUR TIME
PLAYING WITH KNIVES,
YOU'RE NOT EVEN GOOD.
PUT AN APPLE ON YOUR HEAD AND
WE'LL FIND OUT HOW GOOD I AM.
BY THE WAY, UNCLE'S COMING HOME.
DOES THAT MEAN WE WON THE WAR?
NO, IT MEANS UNCLE'S
A QUITTER AND A LOSER.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
UNCLE'S NOT A QUITTER.
OH, YES HE IS.
HE FOUND OUT HIS SON DIED
AND HE JUST FELL APART.
A REAL GENERAL WOULD STAY AND
BURN BA SING SE TO THE GROUND.
NOT LOSE THE BATTLE
AND COME HOME CRYING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT HE SHOULD DO?
HE'S PROBABLY JUST SAD
HIS ONLY KID IS GONE.
FOREVER.
Mother: YOUR FATHER HAS
REQUESTED AN AUDIENCE WITH
FIRE LORD AZULON.
BEST CLOTHES, HURRY UP.
"FIRE LORD AZULON."
CAN'T YOU JUST
CALL HIM GRANDFATHER?
HE'S NOT EXACTLY THE POWERFUL
FIRE LORD HE USED TO BE.
SOMEONE WILL PROBABLY END UP
TAKING HIS PLACE, SOON.
YOUNG LADY.
NOT ANOTHER WORD.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH THAT CHILD?
Man: AND HOW WAS IT
GREAT-GRANDFATHER SOZIN MANAGED
TO WIN THE BATTLE OF HAN TUI?
GREAT-GRANDFATHER WON...
BECAUSE...
BECAUSE EVEN THOUGH
HIS ARMY WAS OUTNUMBERED
HE CLEVERLY CALCULATED
HIS ADVANTAGES.
THE ENEMY WAS DOWNWIND,
AND THERE WAS A DROUGHT.
THEIR DEFENSES BURNED TO A CRISP
IN MINUTES.
Man: CORRECT, MY DEAR.
NOW, WOULD YOU SHOW GRANDFATHER
THE NEW MOVES YOU DEMONSTRATED
TO ME?
SHE'S A TRUE PRODIGY.
JUST LIKE HER GRANDFATHER
FOR WHOM SHE'S NAMED.
[WHISPERS:] You'll never
catch up.
I'D LIKE TO DEMONSTRATE
WHAT I'VE BEEN LEARNING.
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHES HEAVILY]
Zuko: I FAILED.
NO, I LOVED WATCHING YOU.
THAT'S WHO YOU ARE, ZUKO,
SOMEONE WHO KEEPS FIGHTING
EVEN THOUGH IT'S HARD.
Fire Lord Azulon: PRICE OZAI,
WHY ARE YOU WASTING MY TIME
WITH THIS POMP?
JUST TELL ME WHAT YOU WANT.
EVERYONE ELSE, GO.
Zuko: WHAT ARE YOU...
SHH.
Ozai: FATHER.
YOU MUST HAVE REALIZED,
AS I HAVE
THAT WITH LU TEN GONE,
IROH'S BLOODLINE HAS ENDED.
AFTER HIS SON'S DEATH,
MY BROTHER ABANDONED THE SIEGE
AT BA SING SE.
AND WHO KNOWS
WHEN HE WILL RETURN HOME?
BUT I AM HERE, FATHER.
AND MY CHILDREN ARE ALIVE.
SAY WHAT IT IS YOU WANT.
Ozai: FATHER,
REVOKE IROH'S BIRTHRIGHT.
I AM YOUR HUMBLE SERVANT
HERE TO SERVE YOU
AND OUR NATION.
USE ME.
YOU DARE SUGGEST I BETRAY IROH?
MY FIRSTBORN?
DIRECTLY AFTER THE DEMISE
OF HIS ONLY BELOVED SON?
I THINK IROH
HAS SUFFERED ENOUGH.
BUT YOU?
YOUR PUNISHMENT
HAS SCARCELY BEGUN!
[FIRE CRACKLES]
[DOOR OPENS]
♪ DAD'S GOING TO KILL YOU. ♪
REALLY, HE IS.
Zuko: HA, HA, AZULA, NICE TRY.
FINE, DON'T BELIEVE ME.
BUT I HEARD EVERYTHING.
GRANDFATHER SAID DAD'S
PUNISHMENT SHOULD FIT HIS CRIME.
"YOU MUST KNOW THE PAIN
OF LOSING A FIRSTBORN SON.
BY SACRIFICING YOUR OWN."
LIAR.
I'M ONLY TELLING YOU
FOR YOUR OWN GOOD.
I KNOW.
MAYBE YOU COULD FIND
A NICE EARTH KINGDOM FAMILY
TO ADOPT YOU.
STOP IT, YOU'RE LYING.
DAD WOULD NEVER DO THAT TO ME.
Mother: YOUR FATHER WOULD NEVER
DO WHAT TO YOU?
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S TIME FOR A TALK.
AZULA ALWAYS LIES,
AZULA ALWAYS LIES.
[OSTRICH HORSE GRUNTS]
YOU HAVE TO HELP.
IT'S LEE, THE THUGS FROM TOWN
CAME BACK AS SOON AS GANSU LEFT.
WHEN THEY ORDERED US
TO GIVE THEM FOOD,
LEE PULLED A KNIFE ON THEM.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE HE GOT A KNIFE.
THEN THEY TOOK HIM AWAY.
THEY TOLD ME IF
LEE'S OLD ENOUGH TO FIGHT
[CRIES]
HE'S OLD ENOUGH
TO JOIN THE ARMY.
I KNOW WE BARELY
KNOW YOU, BUT...
[CRIES]
Zuko: I'LL GET YOUR SON BACK.
HEY, THERE HE IS!
I TOLD YOU HE'D COME.
[GRUNTS-SQUAWKS]
LET THE KID GO.
[LAUGHS]
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
TELLING US WHAT TO DO?
Zuko: IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHO I AM.
BUT I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
YOU'RE NOT SOLDIERS.
YOU'RE BULLIES.
FREELOADERS ABUSING YOUR POWER.
MOSTLY OVER WOMEN AND KIDS.
YOU DON'T WANT LEE IN YOUR ARMY.
YOU'RE SICK COWARDS MESSING WITH
A FAMILY WHO'S ALREADY LOST
ONE SON TO THE WAR.
ARE YOU GONNA LET THIS STRANGER
STAND THERE AND INSULT YOU
LIKE THIS?
[MAN GRUNTS]
[MAN WHIMPERS]
[MAN ROARS]
[MAN GRUNTS]
[MAN WHIMPERS]
[MAN GROWLS]
HUH?
[MAN SCREAMS]
[LEE LAUGHS]
[GOW GRUNTS]
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
GIVE HIM A LEFT!
A LEFT!
IT'S NOT A FISTFIGHT.
HE'S GOT A LEFT SWORD, DON'T HE?
[GOW GRUNTS]
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
LOOK OUT!
BEHIND YOU!
[GOW GRUNTS]
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
MOM?
ZUKO, PLEASE, MY LOVE,
LISTEN TO ME.
EVERYTHING I'VE DONE,
I'VE DONE TO PROTECT YOU.
REMEMBER THIS, ZUKO.
NO MATTER HOW THINGS
MAY SEEM TO CHANGE
NEVER FORGET WHO YOU ARE.
[WHISPERS:] Get up.
[ZUKO SCREAMS]
[GOW GRUNTS]
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
WHO, WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS ZUKO.
SON OF URSA AND FIRE LORD OZAI.
PRINCE OF THE FIRE NATION
AND HEIR TO THE THRONE.
Crowd: PRINCE OF
THE FIRE NATION?
LIAR!
I HEARD OF YOU,
YOU'RE NOT A PRINCE,
YOU'RE AN OUTCAST.
HIS OWN FATHER BURNED
AND DISOWNED HIM.
[GOW WHIMPERS]
NOT A STEP CLOSER.
IT'S YOURS, YOU SHOULD HAVE IT.
NO, I HATE YOU.
MOM?
MOM, MOM!
WHERE'S MOM?
NO ONE KNOWS.
OH, AND LAST NIGHT,
GRANDPA PASSED AWAY.
NOT FUNNY, AZULA.
YOU'RE SICK.
AND I WANT MY KNIFE BACK, NOW.
[ZUKO GRUNTS]
WHO'S GOING TO MAKE ME?
MOM?
Zuko: WHERE IS SHE?
Man: AZULON, FIRE LORD
TO OUR NATION FOR 23 YEARS
YOU WERE OUR FEARLESS LEADER
IN THE BATTLE OF GARSAI.
OUR MATCHLESS CONQUEROR
OF THE HEW SIN PROVINCES.
YOU WERE FATHER OF IROH.
FATHER OF OZAI.
HUSBAND OF IYLAH, NOW PASSED.
GRANDFATHER OF LU TEN,
NOW PASSED.
GRANDFATHER OF ZUKO AND AZULA.
WE LAY YOU TO REST.
AS WAS YOUR DYING WISH
YOU ARE NOW SUCCEEDED
BY YOUR SECOND SON.
HAIL FIRE LORD OZAI!
♪