Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
IF I WANT TO CATCH MY PREY,
I MUST BE AGILE, NIMBLE.
I NEED A SMALL ELITE TEAM.
EVEN THOUGH I WAS BORN BLIND,
I'VE NEVER HAD A PROBLEM SEEING.
I SEE WITH EARTHBENDING.
Aang: YOU'RE GOING TO BE
A GREAT TEACHER, TOPH.
I THOUGHT A LOT ABOUT
WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU DID? GOOD, GOOD.
WE NO LONGER HAVE
ANYTHING TO GAIN BY
TRAVELING TOGETHER.
I NEED TO FIND MY OWN WAY.
HEY, YOU GUYS PICKED
A GREAT CAMPSITE.
THE GRASS IS SO SOFT.
THAT'S NOT GRASS.
APPA'S SHEDDING.
OH, GROSS.
Aang: THAT'S NOT GROSS.
IT'S JUST A PART OF SPRING.
YOU KNOW, REBIRTH,
FLOWERS BLOOMING,
AND APPA GETS A NEW COAT.
AHH. THE BEAUTY
OF SPRING.
[GROWLING]
STOP. APPA, STOP!
[COUGHING]
IT'S NOT THAT BAD, KATARA.
IT MAKES A GREAT WIG.
Aang: AND A GREAT BEARD.
[BOYS LAUGHING]
I'M JUST GLAD WE FINALLY HAVE
ANOTHER GIRL IN THE GROUP,
BECAUSE YOU TWO ARE
DISGUSTING.
EXCUSE ME.
DOES ANYONE HAVE A RAZOR,
BECAUSE I GOT
SOME HAIRY PITS.
[LAUGHTER]
AH-CHOO!
[CHUCKLES]
SO, TOPH, USUALLY WHEN
SETTING UP CAMP,
WE TRY TO DIVIDE
UP THE WORK.
HEY, DON'T WORRY ABOUT
ME. I'M GOOD TO GO.
WELL, ACTUALLY, WHAT
I'M TRYING TO SAY IS
SOME OF US MIGHT
FETCH WATER
WHILE SOMEONE ELSE
MIGHT SET UP
THE FIRE PIT
OR PUT UP THE TENT.
EVEN MOMO DOES
HIS FAIR SHARE.
KATARA, I'M FINE. I
CAN CARRY MY OWN WEIGHT.
I DON'T NEED A FIRE.
I'VE ALREADY COLLECTED
MY OWN FOOD.
AND LOOK. MY TENT'S
ALL SET UP.
WELL, THAT'S
GREAT FOR YOU, BUT WE
STILL NEED TO FINISH--
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM HERE?
NEVER MIND.
OOPS. SORRY.
HEY, TOPH, I
WANTED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR EARLIER.
I THINK WE'RE ALL
JUST A LITTLE TIRED
AND GETTING ON EACH
OTHER'S NERVES.
YEAH. YOU DO SEEM
PRETTY TIRED.
I MEANT ALL OF US.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT.
THERE'S SOMETHING
COMING TOWARD US.
Aang: WHAT IS IT?
IT FEELS LIKE AN AVALANCHE,
BUT ALSO NOT AN AVALANCHE.
YOUR POWERS OF PERCEPTION
ARE FRIGHTENING.
Katara: SHOULD
WE LEAVE?
Aang: BETTER SAFE
THAN SORRY.
WHAT IS
THAT THING?
[SNORING]
[YAWNS]
LAND, SWEET LAND.
SEE YOU GUYS
IN THE MORNING.
ACTUALLY, CAN YOU
HELP US UNLOAD?
REALLY? YOU NEED ME
TO HELP UNLOAD
SOKKA'S
FUNKY-SMELLING
SLEEPING BAG?
[SNIFFS]
WELL, YEAH.
THAT
AND EVERYTHING ELSE.
YOU'RE A PART OF
OUR TEAM NOW AND--
LOOK, I DIDN'T
ASK YOU TO UNLOAD
MY STUFF.
I'M CARRYING
MY OWN WEIGHT.
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
EVER SINCE YOU JOINED US,
YOU'VE BEEN NOTHING
BUT SELFISH AND UNHELPFUL.
WHAT? LOOK HERE,
SUGAR QUEEN.
I GAVE UP
EVERYTHING I HAD
SO THAT I COULD
TEACH AANG
EARTHBENDING.
SO DON'T YOU TALK
TO ME ABOUT BEING
SELFISH.
"SUGAR QUEEN"?!
D--DID YOU JUST
SLAM THE DOOR IN MY FACE?
HOW CAN YOU BE
SO INFURIATING?
SHOULD WE
DO SOMETHING?
HEY, I'M JUST
ENJOYING THE SHOW.
OK, OK. YOU BOTH
NEED TO CALM DOWN.
BOTH?! I'M
COMPLETELY CALM!
I CAN SEE THAT.
THE STARS SURE ARE
BEAUTIFUL TONIGHT.
TOO BAD YOU CAN'T
SEE THEM, TOPH.
[TOPH GRUNTS]
[KATARA SCREAMS]
HEY, HOW'S A GUY
SUPPOSED TO SLEEP
WITH ALL
THIS YELLING
AND EARTHQUAKING?
THAT THING
IS BACK.
WELL, HOW FAR
AWAY IS IT?
MAYBE WE CAN
CLOSE OUR EYES JUST
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
Aang: I DON'T
THINK SO, SOKKA.
SERIOUSLY, WHAT
IS THAT THING?
AND HOW DOES IT
KEEP FINDING US?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT THIS TIME,
I'M GONNA MAKE SURE
WE LOSE THEM.
Sokka: OK, FORGET ABOUT
SETTING UP CAMP.
I'M FINDING
THE SOFTEST PILE OF DIRT
AND GOING TO SLEEP.
THAT'S GOOD,
BECAUSE TOPH WASN'T
GOING TO HELP ANYWAY.
OH, I DIDN'T REALIZE
BABY STILL NEEDED SOMEONE
TO TUCK HER IN BED.
COME ON, GUYS.
THERE'S SOMETHING
AFTER US,
AND WE DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHAT OR WHO
IT IS.
IT COULD BE ZUKO.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN HIM
SINCE THE NORTH POLE.
WHO'S ZUKO?
OH, JUST SOME ANGRY FREAK
WITH A PONYTAIL
WHO'S TRACKED US
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH PONYTAILS,
PONYTAIL?
THIS IS A WARRIOR'S
WOLF TAIL.
WELL, IT CERTAINLY
TELLS THE OTHER
WARRIORS
THAT YOU'RE FUN
AND PERKY.
ANYWAY, WHOEVER'S
CHASING US, THEY COULDN'T
HAVE FOLLOWED US HERE,
SO, NOW, WOULD
EVERYONE JUST SHUSH?
[MOMO CHATTERING]
NO, MOMO. SHH.
SLEEPY TIME.
OH, DON'T TELL ME.
Aang: THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE'S NO WAY THEY
COULD HAVE TRACKED US.
I CAN FEEL IT WITH
MY OWN TWO FEET.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
MAYBE WE SHOULD FACE THEM
AND FIND OUT WHO THEY ARE.
WHO KNOWS? MAYBE
THEY'RE FRIENDLY.
ALWAYS THE OPTIMIST.
[LIZARDS HISSING]
IT'S THOSE 3 GIRLS
FROM OMASHU.
WE CAN TAKE
THEM--THREE
ON THREE.
ACTUALLY, TOPH,
THERE'S FOUR OF US.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T
COUNT YOU.
YOU KNOW, NO
BENDING AND ALL.
I CAN STILL FIGHT!
OK, 3 ON
3 PLUS SOKKA.
[SOKKA GROWLS]
WELL, WE WANTED TO FIND
OUT WHO THEY WERE,
AND WE FOUND OUT.
NOW, LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
APPA, YIP YIP!
Katara: I CAN'T BELIEVE
THOSE GIRLS FOLLOWED US
ALL THE WAY FROM OMASHU.
I STILL THINK WE
COULD HAVE TAKEN THEM.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THE CRAZY BLUE
FIREBENDING
AND THE FLYING DAGGERS
ARE BAD ENOUGH,
BUT THE LAST TIME WE
SAW THEM,
ONE OF THOSE GIRLS
DID SOMETHING THAT
TOOK MY BENDING AWAY.
THAT'S SCARY.
Sokka: OH, NO.
THE SUN IS RISING.
WE'VE BEEN UP ALL NIGHT
WITH NO SLEEP.
SOKKA, WE'LL
BE OK.
ARE YOU SURE?
I'VE NEVER NOT SLEPT BEFORE.
WHAT IF I FALL ASLEEP NOW
AND SOMETHING HAPPENS?
AND SOMETHING ALWAYS HAPPENS!
EVERY TIME WE LAND,
THOSE GIRLS ARE THERE.
SO WE'LL JUST HAVE
TO KEEP FLYING.
Aang: WE CAN'T KEEP
FLYING FOREVER.
[CALLING]
[AANG YAWNS]
SO WHAT'S OUR PLAN?
DON'T KNOW.
TOO TIRED
TO THINK.
I'M SURE WE'LL COME
UP WITH SOMETHING
AFTER A SHORT NAP.
YES! SLEEP.
WHAT'S GOING ON?!
APPA FELL ASLEEP.
[KIDS SCREAMING]
WAKE UP, BUDDY!
AAH!
APPA'S EXHAUSTED.
OK, WE'VE PUT A LOT
OF DISTANCE BETWEEN
US AND THEM.
THE PLAN RIGHT NOW
IS TO FOLLOW APPA'S LEAD
AND GET SOME SLEEP.
Katara: OF COURSE,
WE COULD HAVE GOTTEN
SOME SLEEP EARLIER
IF TOPH DIDN'T HAVE
SUCH ISSUES.
WHAT?!
ALL RIGHT, ALL
RIGHT! EVERYONE'S
EXHAUSTED.
LET'S JUST GET
SOME REST.
NO. I WANT TO HEAR
WHAT KATARA HAS TO SAY.
YOU THINK I HAVE ISSUES?
I'M JUST SAYING, MAYBE IF
YOU HELPED OUT EARLIER,
WE COULD HAVE SET UP
OUR CAMP FASTER
AND GOTTEN SOME SLEEP.
AND THEN MAYBE WE WOULDN'T
BE IN THIS SITUATION.
Toph: YOU'RE BLAMING
ME FOR THIS?
NO. NO! SHE'S NOT
BLAMING YOU.
NO, I'M BLAMING HER.
HEY!
UH!
I NEVER ASKED YOU FOR
DIDDLY-DOODA.
I CARRY MY OWN WEIGHT.
BESIDES, IF THERE'S
ANYONE TO BLAME,
IT'S SHEDDY OVER HERE.
Aang: WHAT? YOU'RE
BLAMING APPA?
YEAH. YOU WANT TO KNOW
HOW THEY KEEP FINDING US?
HE'S LEAVING A TRAIL
EVERYWHERE WE GO.
HOW DARE YOU BLAME APPA.
HE SAVED YOUR LIFE
3 TIMES TODAY.
IF THERE'S ANYONE
TO BLAME, IT'S YOU.
YOU'RE ALWAYS TALKING
ABOUT HOW YOU CARRY
YOUR OWN WEIGHT,
BUT YOU'RE NOT. HE IS.
APPA'S CARRYING
YOUR WEIGHT.
HE NEVER HAD A PROBLEM
FLYING WHEN IT WAS JUST
THE THREE OF US.
I'M OUT OF HERE.
WAIT.
WHAT DID I JUST DO?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I YELLED AT MY
EARTHBENDING TEACHER.
NOW SHE'S GONE.
I KNOW. WE'RE ALL
JUST TRYING TO GET
USED TO EACH OTHER.
AND I WAS SO MEAN TO HER.
YEAH, YOU TWO WERE
PRETTY MUCH JERKS.
THANKS, SOKKA.
NO PROBLEM.
WE NEED TO FIND
TOPH AND APOLOGIZE.
OK, BUT WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO
ABOUT THE TANK FULL
OF DANGEROUS LADIES
CHASING US?
I HAVE A PLAN.
UGH.
Aang: TOPH WAS RIGHT.
APPA'S FUR WAS LEAVING
A TRAIL RIGHT TO US.
BUT NOW THAT HE'S CLEAN,
NO MORE TRAIL.
Katara: ARE YOU SURE
HE'S OK TO FLY?
HE'LL BE FINE AS LONG
AS WE LEAVE HIS SADDLE
AND ALL OUR STUFF HERE.
I'M GONNA USE APPA'S FUR
TO MAKE A FAKE TRAIL AND LEAD
THE TANK OFF COURSE.
UH!
OHH.
THAT REALLY HURT MY TAILBONE.
WADS OF WET FUR.
HOW DELIGHTFUL.
HMM, THEY'RE NOT WADS.
THEY'RE MORE LIKE BUNDLES.
OR BUNCHES?
IT'S GOT
AN "UH" SOUND.
CLUMPS?
CLUMPS! THEY'RE CLUMPS!
THE TRAIL GOES THIS WAY.
THE AVATAR IS TRYING
TO GIVE US THE SLIP.
YOU TWO HEAD IN THAT DIRECTION
AND KEEP YOUR EYE OUT
FOR THE BISON.
I'LL FOLLOW THIS TRAIL.
TOPH COULDN'T HAVE
MADE IT TOO FAR.
[SCREECHES]
WHAT IS IT,
MOMO?! OH, NO!
KATARA!
HOW DID THEY FIND US?
Sokka: APPA, COME ON.
WE NEED TO GO FASTER.
HE'S TOO TIRED.
NOT GOOD, NOT GOOD!
WE JUST NEED TO MAKE IT
ACROSS THAT RIVER.
COME ON, APPA! JUST
A LITTLE FURTHER.
WHOA!
Sokka: WE MADE IT.
WE'RE SAFE.
YOU DID IT,
APPA!
GOOD TRY, BUT NO.
HOW YOU DOING?
WELL, YOU KNOW.
I THOUGHT WHEN
TY LEE AND I FINALLY
CAUGHT YOU GUYS,
IT WOULD BE MORE
EXCITING.
OH, WELL, VICTORY
IS BORING.
AAH!
THANKS, APPA.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
WE'D DO WITHOUT YOU.
WAS IT JUST ME,
OR WAS THAT GUY
KIND OF CUTE?
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'VE CAUGHT UP WITH ME.
NOW, WHO ARE YOU,
AND WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU MEAN, YOU HAVEN'T
GUESSED? YOU DON'T SEE
THE FAMILY RESEMBLANCE.
HERE'S A HINT.
[IMITATING ZUKO]
I MUST FIND THE AVATAR
TO RESTORE MY HONOR.
[REGULAR VOICE]
IT'S OK. YOU CAN LAUGH.
IT'S FUNNY.
SO WHAT NOW?
NOW? NOW IT'S OVER.
YOU'RE TIRED, AND YOU
HAVE NO PLACE TO GO.
YOU CAN RUN,
BUT I'LL CATCH YOU.
I'M NOT RUNNING.
HERE IS YOUR TEA.
YOU SEEM A LITTLE
TOO YOUNG TO BE
TRAVELING ALONE.
YOU SEEM
A LITTLE TOO OLD.
HA HA HA!
PERHAPS I AM.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING,
I LOOK LIKE I CAN'T HANDLE
BEING BY MYSELF.
I WASN'T THINKING THAT.
YOU WOULDN'T LET ME POUR
MY OWN CUP OF TEA.
I POURED YOUR TEA
BECAUSE I WANTED TO
AND FOR NO
OTHER REASON.
PEOPLE SEE ME
AND THINK I'M WEAK.
THEY WANT TO TAKE
CARE OF ME,
BUT I CAN TAKE CARE
OF MYSELF BY MYSELF.
YOU SOUND LIKE
MY NEPHEW,
ALWAYS THINKING
YOU NEED TO DO THINGS
ON YOUR OWN
WITHOUT
ANYONE'S SUPPORT.
THERE IS NOTHING WRONG
WITH LETTING PEOPLE
WHO LOVE YOU HELP YOU.
NOT THAT I LOVE YOU.
WELL, I JUST MET YOU.
[CHUCKLES]
SO WHERE IS YOUR NEPHEW?
I'VE BEEN TRACKING
HIM ACTUALLY.
IS HE LOST?
YES, A LITTLE BIT.
HIS LIFE HAS
RECENTLY CHANGED,
AND HE'S GOING THROUGH
VERY DIFFICULT TIMES.
HE'S TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHO HE IS,
AND HE WENT AWAY.
SO NOW YOU'RE
FOLLOWING HIM.
I KNOW HE DOESN'T WANT
ME AROUND RIGHT NOW,
BUT IF HE NEEDS ME,
I'LL BE THERE.
YOUR NEPHEW
IS VERY LUCKY,
EVEN IF HE
DOESN'T KNOW IT.
THANK YOU.
MY PLEASURE.
SHARING TEA WITH
A FASCINATING STRANGER
IS ONE OF LIFE'S
TRUE DELIGHTS.
NO. THANK YOU
FOR WHAT YOU SAID.
IT HELPED ME.
I'M GLAD.
OH, AND ABOUT
YOUR NEPHEW,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
TELL HIM THAT YOU
NEED HIM, TOO.
[LIZARD HISSING]
DO YOU REALLY WANT
TO FIGHT ME?
YES. I REALLY DO.
ZUKO!
I WAS WONDERING
WHEN YOU'D
SHOW UP, ZU-ZU.
HA HA. ZU-ZU?
BACK OFF, AZULA. HE'S MINE.
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
[YELLS]
WHOA! AAH!
AAH!
KATARA!
UNCLE.
GET UP.
I THOUGHT YOU GUYS COULD
USE A LITTLE HELP.
THANKS.
WELL, LOOK AT THIS.
ENEMIES AND TRAITORS
ALL WORKING TOGETHER.
I'M DONE.
I KNOW WHEN I'M BEATEN.
YOU GOT ME. A PRINCESS
SURRENDERS WITH HONOR.
AAH!
[YELLS]
GET AWAY FROM US!
ZUKO, I CAN HELP.
LEAVE!
♪