Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
EVEN THOUGH I WAS BORN BLIND,
I'VE NEVER HAD A PROBLEM SEEING.
I SEE WITH EARTHBENDING.
LOOK HERE,
SUGAR QUEEN,
I GAVE UP
EVERYTHING I HAD
SO THAT I COULD
TEACH AANG
EARTHBENDING.
WELL, LOOK AT THIS.
ENEMIES AND TRAITORS
ALL WORKING TOGETHER.
AAH!
TODAY'S THE DAY.
CAN YOU BELIEVE IT?
AFTER ALL THAT TIME
SEARCHING FOR A TEACHER,
I'M FINALLY
STARTING EARTHBENDING.
AND THIS PLACE,
IT'S PERFECT.
DON'T YOU THINK?
SOKKA?
[GROWLS]
OH, YOU'RE STILL
SLEEPING, HUH?
[WHISPERS]
SORRY.
GOOD MORNING,
EARTHBENDING STUDENT.
SIFU TOPH.
HEY, YOU NEVER
CALL ME
SIFU KATARA.
WELL, IF YOU THINK I SHOULD.
[SOKKA GROWLS]
SORRY, SNOOZLES.
WE'LL DO OUR EARTHBENDING
AS QUIETLY AS WE CAN.
AAH!
[GRUMBLING]
RUNNING AROUND
AND MAKING NOISES
SO WHAT MOVE
ARE YOU GONNA
TEACH ME FIRST?
ROCKALANCHE, THE TREMBLER?
OH, MAYBE I CAN LEARN
TO MAKE A WHIRLPOOL
OUT OF LAND.
WELL, LET'S START
WITH, MOVE A ROCK.
SOUNDS GOOD.
THE KEY TO EARTHBENDING
IS YOUR STANCE.
YOU'VE GOT TO BE
STEADY AND STRONG.
ROCK IS A STUBBORN
ELEMENT.
IF YOU'RE
GOING TO MOVE IT,
YOU'VE GOT TO BE
LIKE A ROCK YOURSELF.
LIKE A ROCK. GOT IT.
GOOD.
NOW, THE ACTUAL MOTION OF
THIS ONE IS PRETTY SIMPLE.
OK, YOU READY TO
GIVE IT A TRY?
I'M READY.
AAH! UH!
Sokka: ROCK
BEATS AIRBENDER.
HA HA! I GOT YOU, DAD.
NO! HA HA.
[LAUGHTER]
MY BELOVED LU TEN,
I WILL SEE YOU AGAIN.
UNCLE.
YOU WERE
UNCONSCIOUS.
AZULA DID THIS
TO YOU.
IT WAS A SURPRISE
ATTACK.
SOMEHOW THAT'S NOT
SO SURPRISING.
I HOPE I MADE IT
THE WAY YOU LIKE IT.
[DEADPAN]
GOOD.
[GAGS]
THAT WAS VERY, UM,
BRACING.
SO, UNCLE, I'VE
BEEN THINKING.
IT'S ONLY
A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE I RUN INTO
AZULA AGAIN.
I'M GOING TO NEED
TO KNOW MORE
ADVANCED FIREBENDING
IF I'M GOING
TO STAND A CHANCE
AGAINST HER.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA SAY:
SHE'S MY SISTER AND I
SHOULD BE TRYING
TO GET ALONG WITH HER.
NO. SHE'S CRAZY, AND SHE
NEEDS TO GO DOWN.
IT'S TIME TO RESUME
YOUR TRAINING.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT WENT WRONG.
HE DID IT EXACTLY
THE WAY YOU DID.
MAYBE THERE'S
ANOTHER WAY.
WHAT IF I CAME
AT THE BOULDER FROM
A DIFFERENT ANGLE?
NO, THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
YOU'VE GOT TO STOP THINKING
LIKE AN AIRBENDER.
THERE'S NO DIFFERENT ANGLE,
NO CLEVER SOLUTION,
NO TRICKITY-TRICK THAT'S
GONNA MOVE THAT ROCK.
YOU'VE GOT
TO FACE IT HEAD-ON.
AND WHEN I SAY HEAD-ON,
I MEAN LIKE THIS.
HYAH!
WHOA.
I'VE BEEN TRAINING AANG
FOR A WHILE NOW.
HE REALLY RESPONDS
WELL TO A POSITIVE
TEACHING EXPERIENCE--
LOTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT
AND PRAISE,
KIND WORDS. IF HE'S
DOING SOMETHING WRONG,
MAYBE A GENTLE NUDGE
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
THANKS, KATARA.
A GENTLE NUDGE.
I'LL TRY THAT.
KEEP YOUR KNEES HIGH,
TWINKLE TOES.
ROCK COLLIDE.
HUH?
ROCKLIKE.
YOU'RE AWFULLY CUTE,
BUT UNFORTUNATELY
FOR YOU, YOU'RE
MADE OF MEAT.
JUST A BIT CLOSER.
[YELLING]
GOTCHA.
YOU ARE ONE LUCKY
LITTLE MEAT CREATURE.
LIGHTNING IS
A PURE EXPRESSION
OF FIREBENDING--
WITHOUT AGGRESSION.
IT IS NOT FUELLED BY
RAGE OR EMOTION
THE WAY OTHER
FIREBENDING IS.
SOME CALL LIGHTNING
THE COLD-BLOODED FIRE.
IT IS PRECISE
AND DEADLY,
LIKE AZULA.
TO PERFORM
THE TECHNIQUE
REQUIRES
PEACE OF MIND.
I SEE. THAT'S WHY
WE'RE DRINKING TEA--
TO CALM THE MIND.
OH, YEAH, GOOD POINT!
[SLOWLY]
I MEAN, YES.
THERE IS ENERGY
ALL AROUND US.
THE ENERGY IS BOTH
YIN AND YANG--
A POSITIVE ENERGY
AND A NEGATIVE ENERGY.
ONLY A SELECT FEW
FIREBENDERS CAN
SEPARATE THESE ENERGIES.
THIS CREATES
AN IMBALANCE.
THE ENERGY WANTS
TO RESTORE BALANCE.
AND IN THE MOMENT
THE POSITIVE
AND NEGATIVE ENERGY
COME CRASHING BACK
TOGETHER,
YOU PROVIDE RELEASE
AND GUIDANCE,
CREATING LIGHTNING.
I'M READY TO TRY IT.
REMEMBER, ONCE YOU
SEPARATE THE ENERGY,
YOU DO NOT
COMMAND IT.
YOU ARE SIMPLY
ITS HUMBLE GUIDE.
BREATHE FIRST.
[INHALES]
HYAH! UH!
Toph: THIS TIME, WE'RE
GOING TO TRY SOMETHING
A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
INSTEAD OF MOVING A ROCK,
WE'RE GOING TO STOP A ROCK.
GET IN YOUR HORSE STANCE.
I'M GOING TO ROLL
THAT BOULDER DOWN AT YOU.
IF YOU HAVE THE ATTITUDE
OF AN EARTHBENDER,
YOU'LL STAY IN YOUR STANCE
AND STOP THE ROCK,
LIKE THIS.
SORRY, TOPH, BUT
ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS REALLY
THE BEST WAY
TO TEACH AANG
EARTHBENDING?
I'M GLAD YOU SAID SOMETHING.
ACTUALLY, THERE
IS A BETTER WAY.
THIS WAY, YOU'LL
REALLY HAVE TO SENSE
THE VIBRATIONS
OF THE BOULDER
TO STOP IT.
THANK YOU, KATARA.
[SARCASTICALLY]
YEAH, THANKS, KATARA.
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
I GUESS I JUST
PANICKED.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
THERE'S NOTHING TO SAY.
YOU BLEW IT.
YOU HAD A PERFECT STANCE
AND PERFECT FORM,
BUT WHEN IT CAME
RIGHT DOWN TO IT,
YOU DIDN'T HAVE
THE GUTS.
I KNOW. I'M SORRY.
YEAH, YOU ARE SORRY.
IF YOU'RE NOT
TOUGH ENOUGH
TO STOP THE ROCK,
THEN YOU CAN AT LEAST
GIVE IT THE PLEASURE
OF SMUSHING YOU
INSTEAD OF JUMPING OUT
OF THE WAY LIKE
A JELLY-BONED WIMP.
NOW DO YOU HAVE WHAT IT
TAKES TO FACE THAT ROCK
LIKE AN EARTHBENDER?
NO, I DON'T
THINK I DO.
AANG, IT'S
NO BIG DEAL.
YOU'LL TAKE
A BREAK AND TRY
EARTHBENDING
AGAIN WHEN
YOU'RE READY.
BESIDES,
YOU STILL HAVE
A LOT
OF WATERBENDING
TO WORK ON, OK?
YEAH, THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
YEAH, WHATEVER.
GO SPLASH AROUND
UNTIL YOU FEEL BETTER.
WHY CAN'T I DO IT?
INSTEAD OF LIGHTNING, IT
KEEPS EXPLODING IN MY FACE,
LIKE EVERYTHING ALWAYS DOES.
I WAS AFRAID
THIS MIGHT HAPPEN.
YOU WILL NOT BE ABLE
TO MASTER LIGHTNING
UNTIL YOU HAVE DEALT
WITH THE TURMOIL
INSIDE YOU.
WHAT TURMOIL?
ZUKO, YOU MUST
LET GO OF YOUR
FEELINGS OF SHAME
IF YOU WANT YOUR
ANGER TO GO AWAY.
BUT I DON'T FEEL
ANY SHAME AT ALL.
I'M AS PROUD
AS EVER.
PRINCE ZUKO, PRIDE
IS NOT THE OPPOSITE
OF SHAME,
BUT ITS SOURCE.
TRUE HUMILITY IS
THE ONLY ANTIDOTE
TO SHAME.
WELL, MY LIFE
HAS BEEN NOTHING
BUT HUMBLING LATELY.
I HAVE ANOTHER IDEA.
I WILL TEACH YOU
A FIREBENDING MOVE
THAT EVEN AZULA
DOESN'T KNOW,
BECAUSE I MADE
IT UP MYSELF.
YOU PROBABLY THINK I
DESERVE THIS, DON'T YOU?
LOOK, I'M SORRY I HUNTED YOU,
BUT THAT'S JUST THE NATURAL
ORDER OF THINGS.
BIG THINGS EAT SMALLER THINGS.
NOTHING PERSONAL.
BUT THIS TIME,
IT DIDN'T WORK OUT THAT WAY.
[CALLS]
I ADMIT IT, YOU'RE CUTE.
OK, YOU CONVINCED ME.
IF I GET OUT OF THIS ALIVE,
IT'S A KARMICALLY CORRECT
VEGETARIAN EXISTENCE FOR ME.
NO MEAT, EVEN THOUGH MEAT
IS SO TASTY.
HEY, IT LOOKS
LIKE MY KARMA'S
ALREADY PAYING OFF.
THAT'S OK. I GOT IT.
NOW COME BACK,
BOOMERANG.
[CROAKING]
YOU KNOW THIS BLOCK
YOU'RE HAVING IS
ONLY TEMPORARY,
RIGHT?
I DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
YOU DO REALIZE
THAT'S THE PROBLEM,
DON'T YOU?
IF YOU FACE
THIS ISSUE INSTEAD
OF AVOIDING IT...
I KNOW, I KNOW,
I KNOW, I KNOW.
I GET IT, ALL RIGHT?
I NEED TO FACE IT
HEAD-ON LIKE A ROCK.
BUT I JUST CAN'T DO IT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY I
CAN'T, BUT I CAN'T.
AANG, IF
FIRE AND WATER
ARE OPPOSITES,
THEN WHAT'S
THE OPPOSITE OF AIR?
I GUESS IT'S EARTH.
THAT'S WHY
IT'S SO HARD FOR
YOU TO GET THIS.
YOU'RE WORKING
WITH YOUR NATURAL
OPPOSITE.
BUT YOU'LL FIGURE
IT OUT.
I KNOW YOU WILL.
THINK FAST.
EXCELLENT. YOU HAVE
THE REFLEXES OF
A WATERBENDING MASTER.
THANKS, KATARA,
SIFU KATARA.
FIRE IS THE ELEMENT
OF POWER.
THE PEOPLE OF
THE FIRE NATION
HAVE DESIRE AND WILL
AND THE ENERGY
AND DRIVE TO ACHIEVE
WHAT THEY WANT.
EARTH IS THE ELEMENT
OF SUBSTANCE.
THE PEOPLE OF
THE EARTH KINGDOM
ARE DIVERSE
AND STRONG.
THEY ARE PERSISTENT
AND ENDURING.
AIR IS THE ELEMENT
OF FREEDOM.
THE AIR NOMADS
DETACHED THEMSELVES
FROM WORLDLY
CONCERNS
AND FOUND PEACE
AND FREEDOM.
ALSO, THEY
APPARENTLY HAD
PRETTY GOOD SENSES
OF HUMOR.
WATER IS THE ELEMENT
OF CHANGE.
THE PEOPLE OF
THE WATER TRIBE
ARE CAPABLE
OF ADAPTING
TO MANY THINGS.
THEY HAVE A DEEP
SENSE OF COMMUNITY
AND LOVE
THAT HOLDS THEM
TOGETHER THROUGH
ANYTHING.
WHY ARE YOU TELLING
ME THESE THINGS?
IT IS IMPORTANT TO
DRAW WISDOM FROM MANY
DIFFERENT PLACES.
IF WE TAKE IT FROM
ONLY ONE PLACE,
IT BECOMES RIGID
AND STALE.
UNDERSTANDING
OTHERS--THE OTHER
ELEMENTS
AND THE OTHER
NATIONS--
WILL HELP YOU
BECOME WHOLE.
ALL THIS 4 ELEMENTS
TALK IS SOUNDING
LIKE AVATAR STUFF.
IT IS THE COMBINATION
OF THE 4 ELEMENTS
IN ONE PERSON
THAT MAKES THE AVATAR
SO POWERFUL,
BUT IT CAN MAKE
YOU MORE
POWERFUL, TOO.
YOU SEE, THE TECHNIQUE
I AM ABOUT TO TEACH YOU
IS ONE I LEARNED
BY STUDYING
THE WATERBENDERS.
AANG...
I FOUND THESE NUTS
IN YOUR BAG.
I FIGURED YOU
WOULDN'T MIND.
AND BESIDES,
EVEN IF YOU DID,
YOU'RE TOO MUCH
OF A PUSHOVER TO DO
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I DON'T MIND.
I'M HAPPY TO SHARE
ANYTHING I HAVE.
YOU KNOW, I'M REALLY
GLAD YOU FEEL THAT WAY,
BECAUSE I ALSO HAVE
THIS GREAT NEW NUTCRACKER.
ACTUALLY, I'D PREFER
IF YOU DIDN'T--
[SMASH]
THAT'S AN ANTIQUE,
HANDCRAFTED BY
THE MONK--
IT'S A DELICATE
INSTRUMENT.
IT'S NOT THE ONLY
DELICATE INSTRUMENT
AROUND HERE.
OM.
HEY, AANG,
HAVE YOU SEEN--
MEDITATING HERE.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
IT'S ALMOST SUNDOWN,
AND SOKKA ISN'T
BACK YET.
I THINK WE SHOULD
SEARCH FOR HIM.
WE'LL FIND HIM FASTER
IF WE SPLIT UP.
OK, KARMA PERSON OR THING,
WHOEVER'S IN CHARGE
OF THIS STUFF,
IF I CAN JUST GET OUT OF
THIS SITUATION ALIVE,
I WILL GIVE UP MEAT
AND SARCASM, OK?
OW! THAT'S ALL I GOT.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH
MY WHOLE IDENTITY.
SOKKA, THE MEAT AND SARCASM GUY.
BUT I'M WILLING TO BE SOKKA,
THE VEGGIES
AND STRAIGHT-TALK FELLOW.
DEAL?
AANG!
THANK GOODNESS.
HAVE YOU GOT ANY MEAT?
SOKKA, ARE YOU OK?
STOP, STOP!
YOU'RE GONNA PULL
MY FINGERS OFF.
AND I DON'T THINK
THE REST OF ME
IS COMING.
HMM, I BET I CAN AIRBEND
YOU OUT OF HERE.
SERIOUSLY, AANG, I KNOW
YOU'RE NEW AT IT,
BUT I COULD USE A LITTLE
EARTHBENDING HERE.
HOW ABOUT IT?
I CAN'T.
I CAN'T DO IT.
WELL, IF YOU
CAN'T EARTHBEND ME
OUT OF HERE,
GO GET TOPH.
I CAN'T DO THAT EITHER.
YOU CAN'T? WHY NOT?
IT WOULD JUST BE
REALLY...UNCOMFORTABLE.
"UNCOMFORTABLE."
WELL, I WOULDN'T
WANT YOU TO FEEL
UNCOMFORTABLE.
THANKS, SOKKA.
THIS WHOLE
EARTHBENDING THING
REALLY
HAS ME CONFUSED.
THERE'S SO MUCH
PRESSURE.
EVERYONE EXPECTS ME
TO GET IT
RIGHT AWAY.
IT PUTS ME IN
A REALLY AWKWARD
POSITION.
AWKWARD POSITION? I THINK
I KNOW THE FEELING.
IF I TRY, I FAIL.
BUT IF I DON'T
TRY, I'M NEVER
GONNA GET IT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M
CAUGHT BETWEEN A ROCK
AND A HARD PLACE.
HMM, HOW ABOUT THAT?
AANG, THIS IS MY FRIEND,
FUFU CUDDLY POOPS.
FUFU CUDDLY POOPS,
AANG.
AW. WHAT A CUTE NAME
FOR A LITTLE BABY
SABERTOOTH MOOSE LION CUB.
REALLY? HE LOOKS
NOTHING LIKE
A SABERTOOTH
MOOSE LION.
IT'S HARD TO TELL BEFORE
THEIR GIANT TEETH
AND HORNS GROW IN.
WHAT YOU DOING OUT
HERE, LITTLE GUY?
DID YOU LOSE YOUR MAMA?
[ANIMAL GROWLING]
WATERBENDERS DEAL
WITH THE FLOW OF ENERGY.
A WATERBENDER LETS
THEIR DEFENSE BECOME
THEIR OFFENSE,
TURNING THEIR OPPONENT'S
ENERGY AGAINST THEM.
I LEARNED A WAY TO
DO THIS WITH LIGHTNING.
YOU CAN TEACH ME TO
REDIRECT LIGHTNING?
IF YOU LET THE ENERGY
IN YOUR OWN BODY FLOW,
THE LIGHTNING WILL
FOLLOW IT.
YOU MUST CREATE
A PATHWAY FROM
YOUR FINGERTIPS
UP YOUR ARM
TO YOUR SHOULDER,
THEN DOWN
INTO YOUR STOMACH.
THE STOMACH IS
THE SOURCE OF ENERGY
IN YOUR BODY.
IT IS CALLED
THE SEA OF CHI,
ONLY IN MY CASE, IT IS
MORE LIKE A VAST OCEAN.
[LAUGHING]
FROM THE STOMACH, YOU
DIRECT IT UP AGAIN
AND OUT THE OTHER ARM.
THE STOMACH DETOUR
IS CRITICAL.
YOU MUST NOT LET
THE LIGHTNING PASS
THROUGH YOUR HEART,
FOR THE DAMAGE
COULD BE DEADLY.
YOU MAY WISH TO TRY
A PHYSICAL MOTION
TO GET A FEEL FOR
THE PATHWAY'S FLOW,
LIKE THIS.
NOW, ARE YOU
FOCUSING
YOUR ENERGY?
CAN YOU FEEL
YOUR OWN CHI
FLOWING IN,
DOWN, UP, AND OUT?
I THINK SO.
COME ON. YOU GOT
TO FEEL THE FLOW.
EXCELLENT.
YOU'VE GOT IT.
GREAT. I'M READY
TO TRY IT WITH REAL
LIGHTNING.
WHAT? ARE YOU CRAZY?
LIGHTNING IS
VERY DANGEROUS.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS
THE POINT--
YOU TEACHING ME HOW
TO PROTECT MYSELF FROM IT.
YEAH, BUT I'M NOT
GOING TO SHOOT
LIGHTNING AT YOU.
IF YOU'RE LUCKY,
YOU WILL NEVER
HAVE TO USE THIS
TECHNIQUE AT ALL.
[THUNDER]
WELL, IF YOU WON'T HELP ME,
I'LL FIND MY OWN LIGHTNING.
[CALLING]
HEY THERE.
WE FOUND YOUR CUB.
SEE? WE HAVE NO
PROBLEM WITH YOU.
WE'RE FRIENDLY.
[SNORTING]
AANG, THIS IS BAD.
YOU GOT TO GET
ME OUT OF HERE.
AAH!
THIS IS REALLY BAD.
PLEASE, AANG! YOU HAVE
TO EARTHBEND ME OUT.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY.
HYAH! HYAH!
OH, NO.
YOO-HOO! LOOK AT ME!
PLEASE. DON'T LEAVE
ME AGAIN.
I WON'T.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
JUST ENJOYING THE SHOW.
WHAT? YOU WERE
THERE THE WHOLE
TIME?
PRETTY MUCH.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
DO SOMETHING?
SOKKA WAS
IN TROUBLE.
I WAS IN
TROUBLE!
YOU COULD HAVE
GOTTEN HIM OUT
AND HELPED US
GET AWAY.
I GUESS IT JUST
DIDN'T OCCUR TO ME.
ENOUGH. I WANT
MY STAFF BACK.
DO IT NOW.
WHAT?
EARTHBEND,
TWINKLE TOES.
YOU JUST STOOD
YOUR GROUND
AGAINST A CRAZY
BEAST.
AND EVEN MORE
IMPRESSIVE,
YOU STOOD YOUR
GROUND AGAINST ME.
YOU'VE GOT
THE STUFF.
BUT--
DO IT!
HYAH!
YOU DID IT!
YOU'RE AN EARTHBENDER.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
AW. THIS IS
REALLY A WONDERFUL,
TOUCHING MOMENT.
SO COULD YOU GET ME
OUT OF HERE
SO I CAN GIVE YOU BOTH
A BIG SNUGGLY HUG?
NO PROBLEM, SOKKA.
ACTUALLY, YOU
SHOULD PROBABLY
LET ME DO THAT.
YOU'RE STILL
A LITTLE NEW
TO THIS.
YOU MIGHT
ACCIDENTALLY
CRUSH HIM.
YEAH, NO CRUSHING, PLEASE.
YOU FOUND HIM!
THE WHOLE TIME I WAS
IN THAT HOLE,
NOT KNOWING IF I
WOULD LIVE OR DIE,
IT MAKES A MAN THINK
ABOUT WHAT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT.
I REALIZED--
HEY, KATARA, LOOK WHAT I CAN DO.
YOU DID IT!
I KNEW YOU WOULD.
YOU TRIED
THE POSITIVE
REINFORCEMENT,
DIDN'T YOU?
YUP. IT WORKED WONDERS.
[GROWLS]
APPA, APPA, I CAN
EARTHBEND NOW.
THE KEY IS BEING
COMPLETELY ROOTED--
PHYSICALLY AND MENTALLY
UNMOVABLE.
WHOA! UH!
[LAUGHTER]
[THUNDER]
YOU'VE ALWAYS
THROWN EVERYTHING
YOU COULD AT ME.
WELL, I CAN TAKE IT.
AND NOW I CAN GIVE IT BACK!
COME ON!
STRIKE ME!
YOU'VE NEVER HELD BACK BEFORE.
[ZUKO YELLS]
♪♪