Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE 4 NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL 4 ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST,
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR--
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
Aang: OOF.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
I DISCOVERED A HIDDEN LIBRARY.
I TORE THROUGH
SCROLL AFTER SCROLL.
Toph: YOU DID IT!
YOU'RE AN EARTHBENDER.
SOZEN'S COMET WILL RETURN
BY THE END OF THE SUMMER.
AND FIRE LORD OZAI WILL USE
ITS POWER TO FINISH THE WAR
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
YOU MUST DEFEAT THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET ARRIVES.
Sokka:
WHAT'S OUT HERE?
Toph: A LOT,
ACTUALLY. THERE'S
HUNDREDS OF LITTLE--
SHH! I KNOW YOU
CAN SEE UNDERGROUND,
BUT DON'T RUIN THE SURPRISE.
JUST WATCH.
♪♪
♪ EH ♪
HA HA! YEAH!
♪♪
♪ EH! ♪
I'M PUTTING
AN ORCHESTRA TOGETHER.
ORCHESTRA, HUH? WELL...
♪ LA-DI-DA ♪
♪ LAAH ♪
♪ DIIH ♪
♪ DAAH ♪
♪♪
♪ EH ♪
♪ EH! ♪
THIS IS GREAT AND ALL,
BUT DON'T WE HAVE MORE
IMPORTANT THINGS
TO WORRY ABOUT?
WE SHOULD
BE MAKING PLANS.
WE DID MAKE PLANS.
WE'RE ALL PICKING
MINI-VACATIONS.
THERE'S NO TIME
FOR VACATIONS.
I'M LEARNING THE ELEMENTS
AS FAST AS I CAN.
I PRACTICE HARD EVERY DAY
WITH TOPH AND KATARA.
I'VE BEEN TRAINING
MY ARROW OFF.
YEAH. WHAT'S WRONG
WITH HAVING A LITTLE
FUN IN OUR DOWNTIME?
EVEN IF YOU DO MASTER
ALL OF THE ELEMENTS,
THEN WHAT?
IT'S NOT LIKE WE HAVE
A MAP OF THE FIRE NATION.
SHOULD WE JUST HEAD WEST
UNTIL WE REACH
THE FIRE LORD'S HOUSE?
KNOCK, KNOCK!
HELLO, FIRE LORD!
ANYBODY HOME?
I DON'T THINK SO.
WE NEED SOME INTELLIGENCE
IF WE'RE GONNA WIN THIS WAR.
♪♪
♪ LAAH ♪
HEE HEE! ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL FINISH
OUR VACATIONS.
AND THEN WE'LL
LOOK FOR SOKKA'S
INTELLIGENCE.
Aang: YOUR TURN, KATARA.
WHERE WOULD YOU
LIKE TO GO ON
YOUR MINI-VACATION?
HOW ABOUT
THE MISTY PALMS
OASIS?
THAT SOUNDS
REFRESHING.
OH, YEAH, I'VE BEEN THERE.
IT'S A PRISTINE
NATURAL ICE GROUND.
AND I DON'T USUALLY
USE THE WORD "PRISTINE."
IT'S ONE OF
NATURE'S WONDERS.
[SOUNDTRACK MUSIC
SLOWS DOWN]
MUST HAVE CHANGED
OWNERSHIP SINCE
I WAS HERE.
HEH HEH.
PTOOEY!
[GROWLING]
[SNORING]
ONE MANGO, PLEASE.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING WRONG
WITH HAVING ONE OF THOSE
FRUITY BEVERAGES
WHILE WE PLAN OUR STRATEGY.
EXCUSE ME.
NO WORRIES.
I CLEAN UP EASY.
YOU'RE
A LIVING RELIC.
THANKS. I TRY.
AN AIR NOMAD RIGHT
FRONT OF ME.
PROFESSOR ZEI,
HEAD OF ANTHROPOLOGY
AT BA SING SE
UNIVERSITY.
TELL ME...
WHICH OF THE
AIR TEMPLES DO
YOU HAIL FROM?
THE SOUTHERN TEMPLE.
OH, SPLENDID!
NOW, TELL ME,
WHAT WAS THE PRIMARY
AGRICULTURAL PRODUCT
OF YOUR PEOPLE?
UH, ARE FRUIT PIES
AN AGRICULTURAL PRODUCT?
OH! TRULY
FASCINATING. THAT'S
ONE FOR THE JOURNAL.
Sokka: SO, PROFESSOR,
YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY
A WELL-TRAVELED GUY.
DO YOU HAVE A MORE
CURRENT MAP?
OURS SEEMS TO BE
A LITTLE DATED.
CERTAINLY.
WHAT? NO FIRE NATION?
DOESN'T ANYBODY HAVE
A GOOD MAP OF THAT PLACE?
Katara: YOU'VE MADE A LOT
OF TRIPS INTO THE DESERT.
Zei: ALL IN VAIN,
I'M AFRAID.
I'VE FOUND LOST
CIVILIZATIONS ALL OVER
THE EARTH KINGDOM,
BUT I HAVEN'T
MANAGED TO FIND
THE CROWN JEWEL--
WAN-CHI TONG'S LIBRARY.
YOU'VE SPENT YEARS
WALKING THROUGH
THE DESERT TO FIND
SOME GUY'S LIBRARY?
THIS LIBRARY IS MORE
VALUABLE THAN GOLD,
LITTLE LADY.
IT IS SAID TO
CONTAIN A VAST
COLLECTION
OF KNOWLEDGE.
AND KNOWLEDGE...
IS PRICELESS.
[DEADPAN]
HMM. SOUNDS
LIKE GOOD TIMES.
OH, IT IS.
ACCORDING TO
LEGEND,
IT WAS BUILT
BY THE GREAT
KNOWLEDGE SPIRIT
WAN-CHI TONG
WITH THE HELP
OF HIS
FOXY KNOWLEDGE
SEEKERS.
OH, SO THIS SPIRIT
HAS ATTRACTIVE
ASSISTANTS, HUH?
I THINK HE MEANS
THEY LOOK LIKE
ACTUAL FOXES, SOKKA.
Zei: YOU'RE BOTH RIGHT.
HANDSOME LITTLE CREATURES.
WAN-CHI TONG AND HIS
KNOWLEDGE SEEKERS
COLLECTED BOOKS FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD
AND PUT THEM ON DISPLAY
FOR MANKIND TO READ
SO THAT WE MIGHT
BETTER OURSELVES.
IF THIS PLACE HAS BOOKS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD,
DO YOU THINK THEY'VE GOT
INFO ON THE FIRE NATION?
A MAP MAYBE?
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
BUT IF SUCH
A THING EXISTS,
IT'S IN
WAN-CHI TONG'S
LIBRARY.
THEN IT'S SETTLED. AANG,
I DO BELIEVE IT'S MY TURN.
I'D LIKE TO SPEND MY VACATION
AT THE LIBRARY!
UH, HEY, WHAT ABOUT ME?
WHEN DO I GET TO PICK?
Sokka: YOU'VE GOT TO WORK
HERE A LITTLE LONGER
BEFORE YOU'RE QUALIFIED
FOR VACATION TIME.
HMPH.
OF COURSE, THERE'S THE MATTER
OF FINDING IT.
I'VE MADE SEVERAL TRIPS
INTO THE ZI HUANG DESERT
AND ALMOST DIED EACH TIME.
I'M AFRAID THAT DESERT'S
IMPOSSIBLE TO CROSS.
PROFESSOR, WOULD
YOU LIKE TO SEE
OUR SKY BISON?
A SKY BISON? YOU
ACTUALLY HAVE ONE?!
[GROWLING]
SANDBENDERS, SHOO!
AWAY FROM THE BISON!
TELL ME, SKY BISON,
ARE YOU THE LAST
OF YOUR BREED?
OH, DELIGHTFUL! I
ONLY WISH I SPOKE
HIS TONGUE.
OH, THE STORIES
THIS BEAST
COULD TELL.
SHUSH,
CHATTY MONKEY.
WOW. IT SHOULDN'T BE
TOO HARD
TO FIND A PLACE LIKE THIS
OUT HERE.
AH! DOES THIS PLACE
EVEN EXIST?
SOME SAY IT DOESN'T.
SHOULDN'T YOU
HAVE MENTIONED
THAT BEFORE?
GRR!
THERE IT IS!
THAT'S WHAT IT
WILL SOUND LIKE WHEN
ONE OF YOU SPOTS IT.
[APPA GROWLING]
IT SHOULDN'T
BE THIS HARD
TO SPOT
A GIANT ORNATE
BUILDING
FROM THE AIR.
DOWN THERE. WHAT'S THAT?
FORGET IT. IT'S
OBVIOUSLY NOT WHAT
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
THE BUILDING IN THIS
DRAWING IS ENORMOUS.
WHAT KIND OF ANIMAL
IS THAT?
Zei: I THINK THAT WAS ONE
OF THE KNOWLEDGE SEEKERS.
OH, WE MUST BE CLOSE
TO THE LIBRARY.
NO. THIS
IS THE LIBRARY.
LOOK!
IT'S COMPLETELY
BURIED.
Zei: THE LIBRARY IS BURIED?!
MY LIFE'S AMBITION IS
NOW FULL OF SAND.
WELL, TIME TO START
EXCAVATING.
ACTUALLY, THAT WON'T
BE NECESSARY.
THE INSIDE SEEMS TO BE
COMPLETELY INTACT.
AND IT'S HUGE.
Sokka: THAT FOX THINGY
WENT IN THROUGH A WINDOW.
I SAY WE CLIMB UP THERE
AND GIVE IT A LOOK.
I SAY YOU GUYS
GO AHEAD WITHOUT ME.
YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING
AGAINST LIBRARIES?
I'VE HELD BOOKS
BEFORE.
AND I GOT
TO TELL YOU,
THEY DON'T EXACTLY
DO IT FOR ME.
OH, RIGHT. SORRY.
LET ME KNOW IF THEY HAVE
SOMETHING YOU CAN LISTEN TO.
DON'T WORRY, BUDDY.
I'M NOT MAKING YOU GO
UNDERGROUND EVER AGAIN.
YOU CAN STAY
OUT HERE WITH TOPH.
WHAT'S UP?
[CHATTERS]
Zei: OH, IT'S BREATHTAKING.
THE SPIRIT SPARED
NO EXPENSE IN
DESIGNING THIS PLACE.
LOOK AT THOSE
BEAUTIFUL BUTTRESSES.
HEE HEE!
Zei: WHAT'S
FUNNY?
NOTHING. WE JUST
LIKE ARCHITECTURE.
AS DO I.
MY WORD!
THE EXQUISITE MOSAIC
HANDIWORK OF THIS
TILE-RENDERED AVIAN SYMBOL--
EH, NICE OWL.
[RUSTLING]
[CHATTERING]
I KNOW YOU'RE
BACK THERE.
HELLO!
I'M PROFESSOR ZEI,
HEAD OF ANTHROPOLOGY
AT BA SING SE
UNIVERSITY.
YOU SHOULD LEAVE
THE WAY YOU CAME
UNLESS YOU WANT
TO BECOME A STUFFED HEAD
OF ANTHROPOLOGY.
[SPEAKING GIBBERISH]
Sokka: ARE YOU THE SPIRIT
WHO BROUGHT THIS LIBRARY
TO THE PHYSICAL WORLD?
INDEED. I AM WAN-CHI TONG,
HE WHO KNOWS 10,000 THINGS.
AND YOU ARE
OBVIOUSLY HUMANS,
WHICH, BY THE WAY,
ARE NO LONGER
PERMITTED IN MY STUDY.
Aang: WHAT
DO YOU HAVE
AGAINST HUMANS?
HMM. HUMANS
ONLY BOTHER
LEARNING THINGS
TO GET THE EDGE
ON OTHER HUMANS,
LIKE THAT FIREBENDER
WHO CAME TO THIS PLACE
A FEW YEARS AGO,
LOOKING TO DESTROY
HIS ENEMY.
SO WHO ARE YOU
TRYING TO DESTROY?
WHAT? NO, NO,
NO DESTROYING.
WE'RE NOT INTO THAT.
Wan-Chi Tong: THEN WHY
HAVE YOU COME HERE?
UM, KNOWLEDGE FOR
KNOWLEDGE'S SAKE.
IF YOU'RE GOING TO LIE
TO AN ALL-KNOWING
SPIRIT BEING,
YOU SHOULD AT LEAST
PUT SOME EFFORT INTO IT.
I'M NOT LYING!
I'M HERE WITH
THE AVATAR,
AND HE'S THE
BRIDGE BETWEEN
OUR WORLDS.
HE'LL VOUCH
FOR ME.
OW!
UH, YEAH. I'LL VOUCH.
WE WILL NOT ABUSE
THE KNOWLEDGE IN YOUR
LIBRARY, GOOD SPIRIT.
YOU HAVE MY WORD.
HMM. VERY WELL.
I'LL LET YOU PERUSE
MY VAST COLLECTION
ON ONE CONDITION--
TO PROVE YOUR WORTH
AS SCHOLARS,
YOU HAVE TO CONTRIBUTE
SOME WORTHWHILE KNOWLEDGE.
PLEASE ACCEPT THIS
TOME AS A DONATION
TO YOUR LIBRARY.
FIRST EDITION.
VERY NICE.
I HAVE AN AUTHENTIC
WATERBENDING SCROLL.
OH, THESE ILLUSTRATIONS
ARE QUITE STYLISH.
UH, OH! I KNOW.
HA!
I SUPPOSE THAT COUNTS.
OH, GREAT SPIRIT,
CHECK THIS OUT.
TA-DA!
IT'S A SPECIAL KNOT.
THAT COUNTS
AS KNOWLEDGE.
YOU'RE NOT
VERY BRIGHT, ARE YOU?
ENJOY THE LIBRARY.
BRIGHT ENOUGH TO FOOL YOU.
SO, DO YOU LIKE FLYING?
OF COURSE, I'M MORE
COMFORTABLE ON
THE GROUND
WHERE I CAN SEE.
WELL, I DON'T SEE
THE WAY YOU DO.
I FEEL
THE VIBRATIONS
IN THE GROUND
WITH MY FEET.
BUT THIS SAND IS
SO LOOSE AND SHIFTY,
IT MAKES EVERYTHING
LOOK FUZZY.
[GROWLS]
NOT THAT THERE'S
ANYTHING WRONG
WITH FUZZY.
HEY! LOOK AT THESE
WEIRD LION-TURTLE THINGS.
AH, I'VE SEEN
WEIRDER.
AANG, DID YOU KNOW
IN A PAST LIFE,
YOU WERE LEFT-HANDED?
I ALWAYS KNEW
I WAS SPECIAL.
"THE DARKEST DAY
IN FIRE NATION HISTORY."
IT'S GOT A DATE AT THE TOP,
BUT IT DOESN'T
SAY ANYTHING ELSE.
SOKKA, WHERE ARE
YOU GOING?
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE FIRE NATION
ON THEIR DARKEST DAY.
THIS COULD BE PROMISING.
THE INFORMATION
ON THE FIRE NATION
SHOULD BE RIGHT UP HERE.
Aang: FIREBENDERS.
Katara: THEY DESTROYED
EVERYTHING HAVING TO DO
WITH THE FIRE NATION.
THAT'S SO UNFAIR!
JUST WHEN I THINK
I'M ONE STEP AHEAD OF
THE FIRE NATION,
IT TURNS OUT THEY BEAT
US HERE A LONG TIME AGO.
I NEED TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED ON
THE DARKEST DAY.
[WHIMPERING]
HELLO,
LITTLE WEIRD FOX GUY.
Zei: IT SEEMS IT'S
TRYING TO ASSIST YOU.
UM, SURE. I GUESS I'LL
FOLLOW YOU.
THIS ROOM IS A TRUE MARVEL,
A MECHANICAL WONDER.
IT'S A PLANETARIUM
THAT SHOWS
THE HEAVENS MOVING.
Sokka: THIS IS BEAUTIFUL,
BUT HOW IS IT HELPFUL?
MAYBE THESE DIALS
REPRESENT DATES AND TIMES.
SOKKA, TRY ENTERING
THAT DATE FROM THAT
PARCHMENT YOU TOOK.
SHH! KATARA, NOT
IN FRONT OF THE FOX.
HE'S WITH THE OWL.
[WHIMPERS]
WOW! I GOT TO HAND
IT TO YOU, SOKKA,
YOU PICKED
THE BEST MINI-VACATION
FOR SURE.
Katara: HEY, WAIT.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE SUN?
GREAT. YOU MUST
HAVE BROKEN IT.
IT'S NOT BROKEN.
THE SUN IS BEHIND THE MOON.
IT'S A SOLAR ECLIPSE.
IT'S LITERALLY THE DARKEST
DAY IN FIRE NATION HISTORY.
NOW I GET IT.
SOMETHING AWFUL HAPPENED
ON THAT DAY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT,
BUT I DO KNOW WHY.
FIREBENDERS LOSE
THEIR BENDING DURING
A SOLAR ECLIPSE. SORRY.
THAT
MAKES SENSE.
I MEAN, THINK OF
WHAT THE LUNAR
ECLIPSE
AT THE NORTH POLE
DID TO
THE WATERBENDERS.
THIS IS HUGE.
[FOX WHIMPERS]
FINE. YOU EARNED IT.
WE'VE GOT TO GET
THIS INFORMATION
TO THE EARTH KING
AT BA SING SE.
WE'LL WAIT FOR
THE NEXT ECLIPSE.
THEN WE'LL INVADE
THE FIRE NATION WHEN
THEY'RE TOTALLY HELPLESS.
THE FIRE LORD IS GOING DOWN!
MORTALS ARE SO
PREDICTABLE
AND SUCH
TERRIBLE LIARS.
[SOKKA GULPS]
YOU BETRAYED MY TRUST.
FROM THE BEGINNING,
YOU INTENDED TO MISUSE
THIS KNOWLEDGE
FOR EVIL PURPOSES.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IF ANYONE'S EVIL,
IT'S THE FIRE NATION.
YOU SAW WHAT THEY DID
TO YOUR LIBRARY.
THEY'RE DESTRUCTIVE
AND DANGEROUS.
WE NEED
THIS INFORMATION.
YOU THINK YOU'RE
THE FIRST PERSON
TO BELIEVE
THEIR WAR WAS JUSTIFIED?
COUNTLESS OTHERS BEFORE
YOU HAVE COME HERE,
SEEKING WEAPONS
OR WEAKNESSES OR
BATTLE STRATEGIES.
WE HAD NO CHOICE.
PLEASE. WE'RE JUST
DESPERATE TO PROTECT
THE PEOPLE WE LOVE.
AND NOW I AM GOING
TO PROTECT WHAT I LOVE.
Aang: WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
I'M TAKING
MY KNOWLEDGE BACK. NO ONE
WILL EVER ABUSE IT AGAIN.
HE'S SINKING THE BUILDING.
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUT OF HERE!
I'M AFRAID
I CAN'T ALLOW THAT.
YOU ALREADY KNOW TOO MUCH.
AAH!
[KIDS SCREAMING]
[GROWLS]
I ALREADY TOLD YOU.
I DON'T WANT TO SNUGGLE.
LIBRARY'S SINKING.
LIBRARY'S SINKING!
HYAH!
[YELLS]
AAH!
GREAT KNOWLEDGE
SPIRIT, I BEG YOU,
DO NOT DESTROY YOUR
VAST COLLECTION OF
PRICELESS TOMES.
AAH!
WE'VE GOT TO GET BACK
TO THE SURFACE.
SOKKA, LET'S GO.
BUT WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHEN THE NEXT ECLIPSE
IS GONNA HAPPEN.
DON'T BE STUPID.
WE'LL FIND OUT LATER.
NO, WE WON'T.
IF WE LEAVE THIS PLACE,
WE'LL NEVER GET
THE INFORMATION.
AANG, COME WITH ME
TO THE PLANETARIUM.
I NEED COVER.
KATARA, TAKE MOMO
AND GET OUT OF HERE.
BUT--
Sokka: GO!
HURRY, SOKKA!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
WHAT IS IT NOW?
WHO IS THERE?
Aang: WHY ARE WE
DOING THIS?
BECAUSE IF THIS
CALENDAR CAN TELL US
ABOUT ECLIPSES
IN THE PAST, THEN
MAYBE IT CAN PROJECT
WHEN THE NEXT ONE
WILL BE.
YOU CAN'T POSSIBLY
CHECK EVERY SINGLE DATE.
I DON'T HAVE
TO. WE JUST
NEED TO CHECK
EVERY DATE BEFORE
SOZEN'S COMET
ARRIVES,
BECAUSE AFTER THAT,
WELL, TRY NOT TO
THINK ABOUT THAT.
COME ON, ECLIPSE!
Sokka: THAT'S IT--
THE SOLAR ECLIPSE.
IT'S JUST A FEW
MONTHS AWAY.
GOT IT! NOW LET'S
GET TO BA SING SE.
DON'T MAKE ME PUT THIS DOWN.
NO! STOP SINKING!
NO!
I'M SORRY, APPA.
[CHATTERING]
[SCREECHING]
AT LEAST I'LL HAVE
ONE SPECIMEN TO ADD
TO MY COLLECTION.
AAH!
YOUR WATERBENDING
WON'T DO YOU MUCH
GOOD HERE.
I'VE STUDIED
NORTHERN WATER STYLE,
SOUTHERN WATER STYLE,
EVEN FOGGY SWAMP STYLE.
HYAH!
THAT'S CALLED SOKKA STYLE.
LEARN IT.
WAIT! PROFESSOR,
LET'S GO.
I'M NOT LEAVING.
I CAN'T.
I'VE SPENT TOO LONG
TRYING TO FIND
THIS PLACE.
THERE'S NOT
ANOTHER COLLECTION
OF KNOWLEDGE
LIKE THIS ON EARTH.
I COULD SPEND
AN ETERNITY IN HERE.
JUST GO!
[WAN-CHI TONG SCREECHES]
[KIDS SCREAMING]
WE GOT IT.
THERE'S A SOLAR
ECLIPSE COMING.
THE FIRE NATION'S
IN TROUBLE NOW.
WHERE'S APPA?
♪♪