Girl: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN, EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN
BEFORE HE'S READY
TO SAVE ANYONE.
-[LAUGHING]
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪♪
THE AVATAR HAS KIDNAPPED
MY DAUGHTER.
I WANT YOU TO DO
WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO BRING HER HOME.
AUGH!
SANDBENDERS, SHOO!
AWAY FROM THE BISON!
LIBRARY'S SINKING...
LIBRARY'S SINKING!
Sky Bison: [ROARING]
Girl: NO!
I'M SORRY, APPA.
Aang: WHERE'S APPA?
[MOANING]
♪♪
[WIND BLOWING]
[PURRING]
HOW COULD YOU
LET THEM TAKE APPA?
WHY DIDN'T YOU STOP THEM?
Girl: I COULDN'T.
THE LIBRARY WAS SINKING,
YOU GUYS WERE
STILL INSIDE, AND...
YOU COULD'VE COME TO GET US.
I COULD'VE SAVED HIM!
I CAN HARDLY FEEL
ANY VIBRATIONS OUT HERE.
THE SANDBENDERS SNUCK UP ON ME,
AND THERE WASN'T TIME FOR...
YOU JUST DIDN'T CARE!
YOU NEVER LIKED APPA!
YOU WANTED HIM GONE.
AANG, STOP IT.
YOU KNOW TOPH DID ALL SHE COULD.
SHE SAVED OUR LIVES.
WHO'S GONNA SAVE OUR LIVES NOW?
WE'LL NEVER MAKE IT OUT OF HERE.
THAT'S ALL ANY OF YOU GUYS
CARE ABOUT, YOURSELVES.
YOU DON'T CARE WHETHER
APPA IS O.K. OR NOT.
Girl: WE'RE ALL CONCERNED,
BUT WE CAN'T AFFORD
TO BE FIGHTING, NOW.
I'M GOING AFTER APPA.
AANG, WAIT!
WE'D BETTER START WALKING.
WE'RE THE ONLY PEOPLE WHO KNOW
ABOUT THE SOLAR ECLIPSE.
WE HAVE TO GET THAT INFORMATION
TO BA SING SE.
YOU THINK IF WE DIG OUT
THE GIANT OWL,
HE'LL GIVE US A RIDE?
[GAGGING]
MAYBE WE SHOULD MAKE CAMP.
NO, PLEASE, DON'T STOP
JUST FOR ME.
[MOANING]
UH, OOH, HUH.
[PURRING]
WHAT NOW?
COLONEL MONGKE,
WHAT A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
IF YOU'RE SURPRISED WE'RE HERE,
THEN THE DRAGON OF THE WEST
HAS LOST A FEW STEPS.
YOU KNOW THESE GUYS?
SURE, COLONEL MONGKE
AND THE ROUGH RHINOS
ARE LEGENDARY.
EACH ONE IS A DIFFERENT KIND
OF WEAPON SPECIALIST.
THEY ARE ALSO
A VERY CAPABLE SINGING GROUP.
WE'RE NOT HERE
TO GIVE A CONCERT!
WE'RE HERE TO
APPREHEND FUGITIVES.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME TEA FIRST?
I'D LOVE SOME.
HOW 'BOUT YOU, KACHI?
I MAKE YOU AS A JASMINE MAN.
AM I RIGHT?
Colonel Mongke: ENOUGH STALLING,
ROUND 'EM UP!
[GRUNTING]
AH!
IT'S NICE TO SEE OLD FRIENDS.
TOO BAD YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY OLD FRIENDS
THAT DON'T WANT TO ATTACK YOU.
HMM...
OLD FRIENDS
THAT DON'T WANT TO ATTACK ME?
[PANTING]
UNH.
CAN'T YOU WATCH WHERE YOU'RE...
NO.
RIGHT, SORRY.
COME ON, GUYS,
WE'VE GOTTA STICK TOGETHER.
IF I SWEAT ANYMORE,
I DON'T THINK STICKIN' TOGETHER
WILL BE A PROBLEM.
KATARA, CAN I HAVE SOME WATER?
O.K., BUT WE'VE GOTTA TRY
TO CONSERVE IT.
WE'RE DRINKING
YOUR BENDING WATER?
[SMACKING LIPS]
YOU USED THIS ON THE SWAMP GUY!
UH!
IT DOES TASTE SWAMPY.
[SMACKING LIPS]
[BURPING]
I'M SORRY, IT'S ALL WE HAVE.
NOT ANYMORE, LOOK.
SOKKA, WAIT,
YOU SHOULDN'T BE EATING
STRANGE PLANTS.
[GULPING] AHH.
THERE'S WATER TRAPPED
INSIDE THESE.
I DON'T KNOW.
SUIT YOURSELF.
IT'S VERY
THIRST-QUENCHING, THOUGH.
[WITH ECHOING VOICE]:
DRINK CACTUS JUICE.
IT'LL QUENCH YOU.
NOTHING'S QUENCHIER.
IT'S THE QUENCHIEST!
O.K., I THINK YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH.
WHO LIT TOPH ON FIRE?
[PURRING]
UNH!
CAN I GET SOME OF THAT CACTUS?
I DON'T THINK
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
COME ON, WE NEED TO FIND AANG.
Sokka: HOW DID WE GET OUT HERE
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE OCEAN?
Katara: [SIGHING]
APPA!
NO.
NO!
WHAT IS THAT?
WHAT, WHAT IS WHAT?
Sokka: IT'S A GIANT MUSHROOM.
MAYBE IT'S FRIENDLY!
LET'S JUST KEEP MOVING.
I HOPE AANG'S O.K.
[WITH ECHOING VOICE]:
FRIENDLY MUSHROOM!
MUSHY, GIANT FRIEND!
YEAH, A LITTLE, BAREFOOT
BLIND GIRL AND HER FRIENDS
PASSED THROUGH HERE
A FEW DAYS AGO.
DID THEY GIVE YOU ANY INDICATION
WHERE THEY WERE HEADED?
MAYBE YOU COULD GIVE ME
A LITTLE "INCENTIVE"?
YOU SUGGESTING
I BREAK YOUR FINGERS?
THEY WENT IN THE DESERT.
TOO BAD THERE'S ALMOST NO CHANCE
THEY SURVIVED.
MM, THAT'S O.K.,
'CAUSE SHE'S WANTED,
DEAD OR ALIVE.
NO, SHE'S NOT.
I'M CERTAIN HER FATHER
WANTS HER ALIVE.
HEY, LOOK.
FIRE NATION WANTED POSTERS.
SO?
SO, LOOK WHO'S HERE.
Katara: I'M SORRY, AANG.
I KNOW IT'S HARD
FOR YOU RIGHT NOW, BUT WE NEED
TO FOCUS ON GETTING OUT OF HERE.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE?
WE WON'T SURVIVE WITHOUT APPA.
WE ALL KNOW IT.
COME ON, AANG.
WE CAN DO THIS
IF WE WORK TOGETHER,
RIGHT, TOPH?
AS FAR AS I CAN FEEL,
WE'RE TRAPPED IN A GIANT BOWL
OF SAND PUDDING.
I GOT NOTHIN'.
SOKKA, ANY IDEAS
HOW TO FIND BA SING SE?
WHY DON'T WE ASK
THE CIRCLE BIRDS?
[PURRING]
[LAUGHING FAINTLY]
UGH.
WE'RE GETTING
OUT OF THIS DESERT,
AND WE'RE GONNA DO IT TOGETHER.
AANG, GET UP.
EVERYBODY, HOLD HANDS.
WE CAN DO THIS.
WE HAVE TO.
[LAUGHING]
[PURRING]
[WHIRRING]
[♪...]
I THINK WE SHOULD
STOP FOR THE NIGHT.
All: [GROANING]
IS THERE ANY MORE WATER?
THIS IS THE LAST OF IT.
EVERYONE CAN HAVE
A LITTLE DRINK.
[SCREAMING] MOMO, NO,
YOU'VE KILLED US ALL!
Katara: NO, HE HASN'T.
OH, RIGHT, BENDING.
SOKKA, LET ME SEE THE THINGS
YOU GOT FROM THE LIBRARY.
WHAT?
I DIDN'T STEAL ANYTHING!
WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
IT WAS YOU !
YOU RATTED ME OUT!
SOKKA, I WAS THERE.
Aang: IT DOESN'T MATTER.
NONE OF THOSE WILL TELL
US WHERE APPA IS.
NO, BUT WE CAN FIND OUT
WHICH WAY BA SING SE IS.
WE CAN USE THE
STARS TO GUIDE US.
THAT WAY, WE CAN TRAVEL AT NIGHT
WHEN IT'S COOL,
AND REST DURING THE DAY.
JUST TRY TO GET SOME SLEEP.
WE'LL START AGAIN
IN A FEW HOURS.
NO ONE HERE IS GONNA HELP .
THESE PEOPLE JUST LOOK LIKE
FILTHY WANDERERS.
SO DO WE.
AH, THIS IS INTERESTING.
I THINK I'VE FOUND OUR FRIEND.
YOU BROUGHT US HERE
TO GAMBLE ON PAI SHO?
I DON'T THINK THIS IS A GAMBLE.
LET'S TAKE THEM NOW.
THIS PLACE IS FULL OF
DESPERATE CHARACTERS.
IF THEY FIND OUT
WE'RE COLLECTING A BOUNTY,
WE MIGHT HAVE TO FIGHT THEM ALL,
JUST TO KEEP OUR PRIZE.
PATIENCE.
MAY I HAVE THIS GAME?
THE GUEST HAS THE FIRST MOVE.
I SEE YOU FAVOR
THE WHITE LOTUS GAMBIT.
NOT MANY STILL CLING
TO THE ANCIENT WAYS.
THOSE WHO DO
CAN ALWAYS FIND A FRIEND.
THEN LET US PLAY.
WELCOME, BROTHER.
THE WHITE LOTUS OPENS WIDE
TO THOSE WHO KNOW HER SECRETS.
WHAT ARE YOU OLD GASBAGS
TALKING ABOUT?
I ALWAYS TRIED TO TELL YOU
THAT PAI SHO IS MORE
THAN JUST A GAME.
I'M NOT WAITING ALL NIGHT
FOR THESE GEEZERS
TO FINISH YAPPING!
IT'S OVER!
YOU TWO FUGITIVES
ARE COMING WITH ME.
I KNEW IT!
YOU TWO ARE WANTED CRIMINALS
WITH A GIANT BOUNTY
ON YOUR HEADS!
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
HE WOULD HELP.
HE IS, JUST WATCH.
YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING
TO CAPTURE THEM
AND COLLECT ALL THAT GOLD?
GOLD?
UH, MAYBE WE SHOULDN'T...
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[MOANING]
Katara: COME ON, GET UP,
WE NEED TO GO.
[SMACKING LIPS]
YESTERDAY, MY MOUTH
TASTED LIKE MUD.
NOW, IT JUST TASTES LIKE SAND.
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D MISS THE TASTE OF MUD
SO MUCH.
Aang: I'M AWAKE.
I COULDN'T SLEEP.
WELL, WE NEED TO GET MOVING
IF WE WANT TO GET OUT
OF THIS SAND PIT.
APPA!
Sokka: APPA?
BUT WHY WOULD
PRINCESS YUE NEED HIM?
SHE'S THE MOON,
SHE FLIES BY HERSELF.
IT'S JUST A CLOUD.
WAIT, A CLOUD!
HERE, FLY UP AND BEND THE WATER
FROM THAT CLOUD INTO MY POUCH.
WOW, THERE'S HARDLY ANY IN HERE.
Aang: [SHOUTING]:
I'M SORRY, O.K.?
IT'S A DESERT CLOUD,
I DID ALL I COULD.
WHAT'S ANYONE ELSE DOING?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TRYING TO KEEP
EVERYONE TOGETHER.
LET'S JUST GET MOVING.
WE NEED TO HEAD THIS DIRECTION.
OW!
CRUD, I AM SO SICK OF
NOT FEELING WHERE I'M GOING.
AND WHAT IDIOT BURIED A BOAT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DESERT?
A BOAT?
BELIEVE ME, I KICKED IT
HARD ENOUGH TO FEEL
PLENTY OF VIBRATIONS.
[MOANING]
Katara: IT'S ONE OF THE GLIDERS
THE SANDBENDERS USE.
AND LOOK, IT'S GOT
SOME KIND OF COMPASS ON IT.
I BET IT CAN POINT
US OUT OF HERE.
AANG, YOU CAN BEND A BREEZE
SO WE CAN SAIL IT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT!
[LAUGHING]
[PURRING]
IT IS AN HONOR TO WELCOME
SUCH A HIGH-RANKING MEMBER
OF THE ORDER OF THE WHITE LOTUS.
BEING A GRAND MASTER,
YOU MUST KNOW SO MANY SECRETS.
NOW THAT YOU'VE PLAYED PAI SHO,
ARE YOU GONNA DO
SOME FLOWER ARRANGING?
OR SOMEONE IN THIS CLUB
GONNA OFFER SOME REAL HELP?
YOU MUST FORGIVE MY NEPHEW.
HE IS NOT AN INITIATE,
AND HAS LITTLE APPRECIATION
FOR THE CRYPTIC ARTS.
WHO KNOCKS AT THE GUARDED GATE?
ONE WHO HAS EATEN THE FRUIT
AND TASTED ITS MYSTERIES.
I'M AFRAID IT'S MEMBERS ONLY.
WAIT OUT HERE.
[SNIFFING]
Katara: THE NEEDLE
ON THIS COMPASS
DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
POINTING NORTH,
ACCORDING TO MY CHARTS.
[DREAMILY]: TAKE IT EASY,
LITTLE LADY.
I'M SURE THE SAND FOLKS
WHO BUILT THIS BABY
KNOW HOW TO GET AROUND HERE.
[GASPING]
Katara: THAT'S WHAT THE COMPASS
IS POINTING TO.
THAT GIANT ROCK.
IT MUST BE THE MAGNETIC CENTER
OF THE DESERT.
A ROCK?
YES, LET'S GO!
MAYBE WE CAN FIND
SOME WATER THERE.
SOME SANDBENDERS.
AH, FINALLY.
SOLID GROUND.
Sokka: [BREATHING DEEPLY]
I THINK MY HEAD IS STARTING
TO CLEAR OUT THE CACTUS JUICE.
AND LOOK!
PTH, UH, UGH!
TASTES LIKE ROTTEN PENGUIN MEAT.
OH, I FEEL WOOZY.
YOU'VE BEEN HALLUCINATING
ON CACTUS JUICE ALL DAY,
AND THEN YOU JUST LICK SOMETHING
YOU FIND STUCK TO THE WALL
OF A CAVE?
I HAVE A NATURAL CURIOSITY.
I DON'T THINK
THIS IS A NORMAL CAVE.
THIS WAS CARVED BY SOMETHING.
Aang: YEAH, LOOK AT THE SHAPE.
Toph: THERE'S SOMETHING
BUZZING IN HERE.
SOMETHING THAT'S
COMING FOR US!
[SCREAMING]
[WHIRRING OF WINGS]
Insect: [SHRIEKING]
Toph: [GRUNTING]
OH!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THAT ROCK ALMOST CRUSHED ME.
SORRY, I CAN'T TELL
WHERE THEY ARE IN THE AIR.
I GOT THIS ONE.
[SCREAMING]
Katara: SOKKA,
THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
HUH?
I GUESS MY HEAD'S NOT AS CLEAR
AS I THOUGHT.
Katara: WE HAVE
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
I'M COMPLETELY OUT OF WATER
TO BEND.
Aang: MOMO!
I'M NOT LOSING ANYONE ELSE
OUT HERE.
COME ON, WE'RE GOING DOWN.
Insect: [SHRIEKING]
Katara: TOPH, SHOOT A ROCK,
RIGHT THERE.
FIRE!
Insect: [SHRIEKING]
Sokka: YEAH, YOU GOT IT!
SHE GOT IT, RIGHT?
YES.
NOW, LET'S MOVE.
[PURRING]
[GRUNTING]
Katara: ON YOUR LEFT.
Insect: [SHRIEKING]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
IS THE CLUB MEETING OVER?
EVERYTHING IS TAKEN CARE OF.
WE'RE HEADING TO BA SING SE.
BA SING SE?
WHY WOULD WE GO TO
THE EARTH KINGDOM CAPITAL?
THE CITY IS FILLED
WITH REFUGEES.
NO ONE WILL NOTICE TWO MORE.
WE CAN HIDE
IN PLAIN SIGHT THERE.
AND IT'S THE SAFEST PLACE
IN THE WORLD
FROM THE FIRE NATION.
EVEN I COULDN'T
BREAK THROUGH TO THE CITY.
I HAVE THE PASSPORTS
FOR OUR GUESTS,
BUT THERE ARE TWO MEN
OUT ON THE STREET
LOOKING FOR THEM.
YOU SEEN THESE GUYS?
Man: WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN OUR LAND
WITH A SANDBENDER SAILER?
FROM THE LOOKS OF IT,
YOU STOLE IT
FROM THE HAMI TRIBE.
WE FOUND THE SAILER
ABANDONED IN THE DESERT.
WE'RE TRAVELING WITH THE AVATAR.
Katara: OUR BISON WAS STOLEN,
AND WE HAVE TO GET TO
BA SING SE.
YOU DARE ACCUSE
OUR PEOPLE OF THEFT,
WHILE YOU RIDE IN
ON A STOLEN SAND SAILER?
QUIET, GHASHIUN!
NO ONE ACCUSED
OUR PEOPLE OF ANYTHING.
IF WHAT THEY SAY IS TRUE,
WE MUST GIVE THEM HOSPITALITY.
Ghashiun: SORRY, FATHER.
Toph: I RECOGNIZE
THE SON'S VOICE.
HE'S THE ONE THAT STOLE APPA.
ARE YOU SURE?
Toph: I NEVER FORGET A VOICE.
YOU STOLE APPA.
WHERE IS HE?
WHAT DID YOU DO TO HIM?
THEY'RE LYING.
THEY'RE THE THIEVES!
[GRUNTING]
WHERE IS MY BISON?
HEY, YOU.
WHERE ARE THESE MEN?
I GOT A TIP
THAT THEY'RE IN YOUR SHOP.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
NO ONE IS HERE BUT US.
WE KNOW ALL ABOUT
YOUR SECRET BACK ROOM.
KICK IT DOWN.
HEY, THAT ROOM
IS FOR FLOWERS ONLY.
SOME UNLUCKY SOUL
HAS AN INCOMPLETE PAI SHO SET.
[GRUNTING]
LET'S GO BACK
TO FINDING THE GIRL.
Aang: YOU TELL ME
WHERE HE IS, NOW .
WHAT DID YOU DO?
IT WASN'T ME.
Toph: YOU SAID
TO PUT A MUZZLE ON HIM.
YOU MUZZLED APPA?
Ghashiun: I'M SORRY!
I DIDN'T KNOW
IT BELONGED TO THE AVATAR!
[WITH DISTORTED VOICE]:
TELL ME WHERE APPA IS.
Ghashiun: I TRADED HIM
TO SOME MERCHANTS.
HE'S PROBABLY
IN BA SING SE BY NOW.
THEY WERE GONNA SELL HIM THERE.
PLEASE, WE'LL ESCORT YOU
OUT OF THE DESERT.
WE'LL HELP HOWEVER WE CAN.
JUST GET OUT OF HERE, RUN!
♪♪