- KATARA: Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I discovered
the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
- Ugh!
- KATARA: But I believe
Aang can save the world.
♪
- We're heading to Ba Sing Se.
- Why would we go to the
Earth Kingdom capital?
- The city is filled
with refugees.
- Uh, what's Suki up to?
- Actually,
she and the other warriors
left to fight in the war.
- My name's Jet.
The Fire Nation
killed my parents.
I was only eight years old.
That day changed me forever.
- [blast]
- [waves crashing]
- KATARA: All those people.
Jet, you monster!
- JET: This was a
victory, Katara.
The Fire Nation is gone and
this valley will be safe.
- [growls]
- Tell me where Appa is!
- I traded him.
He's probably in Ba
Sing Se right now.
- [gusting]
♪
- [calm music]
- [chirps]
- [gasps]
- Waterbending bomb!
Yeah!
- [splash]
- [ice shatters]
- [laughter]
- Sure, 5,000-year-old maps
from the Spirit Library.
Just splash some water on them.
- Sorry.
- [birds chirping]
- So did you figure out
what route we're gonna take?
- SOKKA: Okay, we just
got out of the desert,
so we must be around here.
And we need to go to
Ba Sing Se, which is here.
It looks like the only passage
connecting the south
to the north
is this sliver of land
called the Serpent's Pass.
- You're sure that's
the best way to go?
- It's the only way.
I mean, it's not like we
have Appa to fly us there.
- Shush up about Appa.
Can't you at least
try to be sensitive?
- Katara, it's okay.
I know I was upset about
losing Appa before,
but I just want to focus on
getting to Ba Sing Se
and telling the Earth King
about the solar eclipse.
- Oh, well, okay.
I'm glad you're doing better.
- Then to Ba Sing Se we go.
No more distractions.
- Hello there, fellow refugees!
- So are you guys headed
to Ba Sing Se too?
- Sure are.
We're trying to get there before
my wife, Ying, has her baby.
- Great.
We can travel through the
Serpent's Pass together.
- The Serpent's Pass?
Only the truly desperate
take that deadly route.
- Deadly route?
Great pick, Sokka!
- Well, we are desperate.
- You should come with
us to Full Moon Bay.
Ferries take refugees
across the lake.
It's the fastest
way to Ba Sing Se.
- And it's hidden so the
Fire Nation can't find it.
- Hm, peaceful ferry
ride or deadly pass?
- [clacking]
- KATARA: I can't believe
how many people's lives
have been uprooted
by the Fire Nation.
- We're all looking
for a bit of life--
- [baby cries]
- --safe behind the walls
of Ba Sing Se.
- [tense music]
♪
- Who would've thought
after all these years
I'd return to the scene
of my greatest military disgrace
as a tourist?
- Look around.
We're not tourists.
We're refugees.
Ugh!
I'm sick of eating rotten
food, sleeping in the dirt.
I'm tired of living like this.
- JET: Aren't we all?
My name's Jet, and these
are my Freedom Fighters,
Smellerbee and Longshot.
- Hey.
- Hello.
- Here's the deal.
I hear the captain's
eating like a king
while all us refugees have
to feed off his scraps.
Doesn't seem fair, does it?
- What sort of king
is he eating like?
- The fat, happy kind.
- [boing sound]
- You wanna help us
liberate some food?
- [splash]
- I'm in.
- I told you already, no
vegetables on the ferry!
One cabbage slug
could destroy the entire
ecosystem of Ba Sing Se!
Security!
- Aah!
- [growls]
- Gah, my cabbages!
[sobs]
- Next!
- Um, four tickets for the
ferry to Ba Sing Se, please.
- Passports?
- Uh, no one told us we
had to have passports.
- Don't you know who this is?
He's the Avatar.
- Ah, I see 50 Avatars a day.
And by the way, not a
very impressive costume.
- [pipe music]
- [squawks]
- Besides, no animals allowed.
Do I need to call security?
- [burps]
- [squeaks and trills]
- That won't be necessary.
- Next!
- I'll take care of this.
My name is Toph Beifung
and I need four tickets.
- Ah, the golden steal
of the flying boar.
It is my pleasure to help
anyone of the Beifung family.
- It is your pleasure.
As you can see,
I am blind and these
three imbeciles are my valets.
- But the animal--
- --is my seeing-eye lemur.
- [chatters]
- Well, normally it's only
one ticket per passport,
but this document
is so official,
I guess it's worth four tickets.
- Thank you very much.
- All right!
We scammed that lady good!
Aah!
- Tickets and passports, please.
- Is there a problem?
- Yeah, I got a
problem with you.
I've seen your type before.
Probably sarcastic,
think you're hilarious.
And let me guess, you're
travelling with the Avatar.
- Do I know you?
- You mean you don't remember?
Maybe you remember this.
- Suki!
- Sokka, it's good to see you!
- KATARA: You look so different
without your makeup
and the new outfit.
- That crabby lady makes all
the security guards wear them.
And look at you, sleeveless guy.
Been working out?
- Oh, I'll grab a tree branch
and do a few chin touches
every now and then.
Nothing major.
- Are the other
Kyoshi Warriors around?
- Yeah.
After you left Kyoshi, we wanted
to find a way to help people.
We ended up escorting
some refugees
and we've been here ever since.
- [chatters]
- [laughs]
Hi, Momo.
Good to see you too.
- [trills]
- So why are you guys getting
tickets for the ferry?
Wouldn't you just
fly across on Appa?
- Appa is missing.
We hope to find
him in Ba Sing Se.
- I'm so sorry to hear that.
Are you doing okay?
- I'm doing fine.
Would everybody stop
worrying about me?
- Avatar Aang, you
have to help us!
Someone took
all of our belongings,
our passports, our tickets.
Everything's gone!
[sobs]
- I'll talk to the lady for you.
- No passports, no tickets!
- But she's pregnant, and
all their stuff was stolen.
You have to make an exception.
- No exceptions!
If I just gave away tickets
willy-nilly to anyone,
there would be no more order.
And you know what that means--
no more civilization!
- What if we gave
them our tickets?
- No!
- But--
- Next!
- [splash]
- Don't worry, you'll
get to the city safely.
I'll lead you through
the Serpent's Pass.
- I can't believe we gave up
our tickets
and now we're going through
the Serpent's Pass.
- I can't believe you're
still complaining about it.
- I'm coming too!
- Are you sure
that's a good idea?
- Sokka, I thought
you'd want me to come.
- I do.
It's just--
- Just what?
- Nothing.
I'm glad you're coming.
This is the Serpent's Pass?
I thought it would be
more wind-y.
You know, like a serpent.
Hm, I guess they misnamed it.
- Look at this writing.
How awful.
- What does it say?
- It says, "Abandon hope."
- How could we abandon hope?
That's all we have.
- AANG: I don't know.
The monks used to say that
hope is just a distraction.
So maybe we do
need to abandon it.
- What are you talking about?
- Hope isn't going to
get us into Ba Sing Se,
and it's not gonna find Appa.
We need to focus on what
we're doing right now,
and that's getting
across this pass.
- Okay, if you say so.
- SUKI: The Fire Nation
controls the Western Lake.
Rumor has it they're working on
something big on the other side
and they don't want anyone
to find out what it is.
- [clacking]
- Whoa!
[groans]
I'm okay!
- [rumbling]
- [splash]
- They spotted us!
Let's go!
- [blasts]
- [gasps]
- [clacking]
- Suki, are you okay?
You have to be more careful!
Come on!
- Thanks for saving
my life, Toph.
Hey, no problem, Sokka.
- ♪
- [pipe music]
♪
- Suki, you shouldn't
sleep there.
Who knows how stable
this ledge is?
It could give way at any moment.
- Sokka, I'm fine.
Stop worrying!
- You're right, you're right.
You're perfectly capable
of taking care of yourself.
Wait!
Oh, never mind.
I thought I saw a spider.
But you're fine.
- [splashing]
- [tense music]
♪
- [clank]
- ♪
- SMELLERBEE: Guard's coming!
- [whistle]
- You know, it's
okay to miss Appa.
What's going on with you?
In the desert, all you cared
about was finding Appa.
And now it's like you don't
care about him at all.
- You saw what I did out there.
I was so angry about losing
Appa, I couldn't control myself.
I hated feeling like that.
- But now you're not letting
yourself feel anything.
I know sometimes it
hurts more to hope,
and it hurts more to care.
But you have to promise me
that you won't stop caring.
Come on, you need a hug.
- AANG: Thank you for
you concern, Katara.
- [gentle music]
♪
- It's a beautiful moon.
- Yeah, it really is.
- Look, I know you're
just trying to help,
but I can take care of myself.
- I know you can.
- Then why are you
acting so overprotective?
- It's so hard to lose
someone you care about.
Something happened
at the North Pole
and I couldn't protect someone.
I don't want anything like
that to ever happen again.
- I lost someone I cared about.
He didn't die.
He just went away.
I only had a few days
to get to know him,
but he was smart,
and brave, and funny.
- Who is this guy?
Is he taller than me?
- No, he's about your height.
- Is he better-looking?
- It is you, stupid!
- Oh.
- [gentle music]
♪
- I can't.
- I'm sorry.
- No, you shouldn't be.
- [waves crashing]
- So, Smellerbee.
That's an unusual
name for a young man.
- Maybe it's because
I'm not a man.
I'm a girl!
- [cymbals clash]
- Oh, now I see!
It's a beautiful name
for a lovely girl!
- I know.
You're right.
As long as I'm
confident with who I am,
it doesn't matter what
other people think.
Thanks, Longshot.
- [slurping]
- From what I heard,
people eat like this
every night in Ba Sing Se.
I can't wait to set my
eyes on that giant wall.
- It is a magnificent sight.
- So you've been there before?
- Once, when I was
a different man.
- I've done some things in my
past that I'm not proud of.
But that's why I'm
going to Ba Sing Se--
for a new beginning,
a second chance.
- That's very noble of you.
I believe people can change
their lives if they want to.
I believe in second chances.
- [pipe music]
♪
- MOMO: [trills]
- ♪
- Everyone single file!
- [water rushing]
- KATARA: Aang, I need help!
- [chatters]
- [bubbling]
- [tense music]
♪
- [splash]
- ♪
- [frightened chatter]
- What is that thing?
- [gasping]
- [screaming]
- [tense music]
♪
- [splash]
- ♪
- [roars]
- I think I just figured out why
they call it the Serpent's Pass!
- [roars]
- Suki, you know about
giant sea monsters.
Make it go away!
- Just because I live
near the Unagi
doesn't mean I'm an expert!
- Oh great and
powerful sea serpent,
please accept this humble
and tasty offering.
Thank you.
- Sokka!
- [screeches]
- I'll distract it.
Katara, get everyone across.
- [roars]
- SERPENT: [roars]
[roars]
[screeches]
- [splash]
- [tense music]
♪
- [roars]
[screeches]
- Toph, come on!
It's just ice!
- Actually, I'm gonna stay on my
little island where I can see.
- [screeches]
- Aah!
Okay, I'm coming!
- SOKKA: You're doing great!
Just follow the
sound of my voice.
- It's hard to ignore.
- SOKKA: You're almost there!
- SERPENT: [roars]
- [screams]
Help!
I can't swim!
- SOKKA: I'm coming, Toph!
- SERPENT: [screeches]
- [pants]
- Help!
- [bubbling]
- [gasps]
Oh, Sokka, you saved me!
Mwah!
- Actually, it's me.
- Oh, well.
[chuckles]
You can go ahead and
let me drown now.
- [roars]
- [tense music]
♪
- [screeches]
[screeches]
- [splash]
- ALL: Yeah!
- There's the wall!
Now it's nothing but smooth
sailing to Ba Sing Se.
- [gasps]
Oh no!
- What's wrong?
- The baby's coming.
- What? Now?
Can't you hold it
in or something?
- Sokka, calm down.
I helped Gran Gran deliver
lots of babies back home.
- This isn't the same as
delivering an arctic seal!
This a real human being!
- It's called a baby.
And I've helped her deliver
plenty of those too.
Aang, get some rags.
Sokka, water.
Toph, I need you to make
an earth tent-- a big one.
- [clacking]
- Suki, come with me.
- You know, as soon
as I saw your scar,
I knew exactly who you were.
You're an outcast, like me.
And us outcasts have
to stick together.
We have to watch each other's
backs, because no one else will.
- I've realized lately
that being on your own
isn't always the best path.
- ♪
- [pants]
- You're doing great, Ying.
Sokka, where's that water?
Now get ready to push.
One, two, three, push!
- YING: [groans]
- [baby crying]
- KATARA: It's a girl!
- So, you wanna go see the baby
or are you going to faint
like an old lady again?
- No, no.
I'm good this time.
- Aang, you have
to come see this.
- [baby crying]
- She sounds healthy.
- She's beautiful.
- And so squishy-looking.
- What should we name her?
- I want our daughter's
name to be unique.
I want it to mean something.
- I've been going through
a really hard time lately.
But you've made
me hopeful again.
- I know what I want
to name our baby now--
Hope.
- That's a perfect name.
- I thought I was
trying to be strong.
But really I was just running
away from my feelings.
Seeing this family together,
so full of happiness and love,
it's reminding me
how I feel about Appa...
...and how I feel about you.
- [gentle music]
♪
- I promise, I'll find
Appa as fast as I can.
I just really need to do this.
- See you in the big city.
- Say hi to that
big fuzzball for me.
- You'll find him, Aang.
- I know.
Thank you, Katara.
- [chatters]
- You ready, Momo?
[chatters]
- Sokka, it's been really
great to see you again.
- Whoa, hold on.
Why does it sound like
you're saying goodbye?
- I came along because
I wanted to make sure
you got through
the Serpent's Pass safely.
But now I need to get back
to the other Kyoshi Warriors.
- So you came along
to protect me?
- Listen, I'm really
sorry about last night.
We were talking
and saying things.
I just got carried away
and before I knew it, I--
- [smack]
- You talk too much.
♪
- MOMO: [chatters]
[chatters]
- [uplifting music]
♪
[chatters]
- [gasps]
- [ominous music]
♪
- Sorry, Momo.
Appa's gonna have to wait.
- [drill whirring]
♪
- [whoosh]
- [creaking]
- [drum beating]
- [whirring]
- ♪
- This drill is a feat of
scientific ingenuity
and raw destructive power.
Once it tunnels
through the wall,
our troops will
storm their city.
The Earth Kingdom
will finally fall.
And you can claim Ba Sing Se
in the name of your father.
Nothing can stop us.
- Hm, what about those
muscle-y guys down there?
- [drill whirring]
- Please, the drill's
metal shell
is impervious to any
earthbending attack.
- Oh, I'm sure it
is, War Minister Qin.
But just to be
on the safe side,
Mai and Ty Lee,
take the Earthbenders out.
- Finally, something to do.
- MOMO: [chatters]
- Aang, what are you doing here?
I thought you were
looking for Appa.
- I was, but something
stopped me-- something big.
- [clacking]
- SOKKA: Now, what's so big
that Appa has to wait?
- AANG: That.
- [drill whirring]
- We made it to Ba Sing Se
and we're still not safe.
No one is.
- What are you
people doing here?
Civilians aren't
allowed on the wall.
- I'm the Avatar.
Take me to whoever's in charge.
- It is an honor to welcome you
to the Outer Wall, young Avatar.
But your help is not needed.
- Not needed?
- Not needed.
I have the situation
under control.
I assure you, the Fire Nation
cannot penetrate this wall.
Many have tried to break through
it, but none have succeeded.
- What about the
Dragon of the West?
He got in.
- Well, technically, yes.
But he was quickly expunged.
Nevertheless, that's why the
city is named Ba Sing Se.
It's the impenetrable city.
They don't call it Na Sing Se!
[laughs]
That means penetrable city.
- Yeah, thanks for the tour.
But we still got
the drill problem.
- Not for long.
To stop it, I've sent an elite
platoon of Earthbenders
called the Terra Team.
- That's a good group name.
Very catchy.
- [grunting]
- [rumbling]
- Ready?
Attack!
- [clacking]
- [creaking]
- [grunting]
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [grunts]
[grunts]
- [grunting]
- [groans]
- We're doomed!
- [smack]
- Get a hold of yourself, man!
- You're right.
I'm sorry.
- Maybe you'd like
the Avatar's help now?
- [meekly]
Yes, please.
- So the question is, how
are we gonna stop that thing?
- Why are you all looking at me?
- You're the idea guy.
- So I'm the only one who
could ever come up with a plan?
That's a lot of pressure.
- And also, the complaining guy.
- That part I don't mind.
- So, Mr. Lee and Mister, um...
"Mushy," is it?
- It's pronounced "Moo-shi."
- You telling me
how to do my job?
- Uh, no, no, no.
But may I just say, you're
like a flower in bloom.
Your beauty's intoxicating.
- Mm, you're pretty easy on
the eyes yourself, handsome.
Rawr!
Welcome to Ba Sing Se.
- I'm gonna forget I saw that.
- I think Lee would make
a good Freedom Fighter.
He's just trying to find his
way in the world, like us.
- You don't know
anything about him, Jet.
- I know he didn't get that
scar from a Waterbender.
- Besides, I thought we
were going straight now.
- We are.
And the new Freedom Fighters
could use a guy like Lee.
What do you think, Longshot?
I can respect that.
- What's wrong with him?
He doesn't look injured.
- His qi is blocked.
Who did this to you?
- Two girls ambushed us.
One of them hit me with
a bunch of quick jabs.
And suddenly, I
couldn't earthbend,
and I could barely move.
And then she cartwheeled away.
- Ty Lee.
She doesn't look dangerous,
but she knows the human body
and its weak points.
It's like she takes you
down from the inside.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
- Yes?
- What you just said.
That's how we're gonna
take down the drill--
the same way Ty Lee took
down all these big Earthbenders.
- By hitting its
pressure points!
- We'll take it down
from the inside.
- [drill whirring]
- Once I whip up some cover,
you're not gonna be able to see,
so stay close to me.
- [rumbling]
- TOPH: Run!
- MOMO: [chatters]
- Hey, look at that dust cloud.
It's so... poofy.
Poof!
- Don't worry, Princess.
I'm sure it's nothing.
- [drill whirring]
- ♪
- [rumbling]
- Everyone into the hole.
- SOKKA: It's so dark down here.
I can't see a thing.
- TOPH: [sarcastically]
Oh, no, what a nightmare!
- SOKKA: Sorry.
- [drill whirring]
- There.
- MOMO: [chatters]
- [grunts]
Toph, come on!
- No way am I going
in that metal monster.
I can't bend in there.
I'll try to slow
it down out here.
- Okay, good luck.
- [rumbling]
- [grunts]
- I need a plan of this machine,
some schematics
that show what the inside
looks like.
Then we can find
its weak points.
- Where are we gonna
get something like that?
- [clang]
- What are you doing?
Someone's gonna hear us.
- That's the point.
I figure a machine this big
needs engineers to run it.
And when something breaks--
- --they come to fix it.
- [whooshing]
- ♪
- Hi.
This'll work, thanks!
- [clang]
- SOKKA: It looks like
the drill
is made up of
two main structures.
There's the inner
mechanism, where we are now,
and the outer shell.
The inner part
and the outer part
are connected by these braces.
If we cut through them, the
entire thing will collapse.
- So, you guys got plans
once you're inside the city?
- MAN: Get your hot tea here!
Finest tea in Ba Sing Se!
- Oh, Jasmine, please!
- [pipe music]
♪
- [coughs]
Coldest tea in Ba Sing Se
is more like it.
What a disgrace!
- Hey, can I talk
to you for a second?
- [sighs]
- You and I have a much better
chance of making it in the city
if we stick together.
You wanna join the
Freedom Fighters?
- Thanks, but I don't think
you want me in your gang.
- Come on, we made a great team
looting that captain's food.
Think of all the good we
could do for these refugees.
- I said no.
- Have it your way.
- [slurps]
- [ominous music]
♪
- Hey!
- What are you doing
firebending your tea?
For a wise old man, that
was a pretty stupid move.
- I know you're not supposed
to cry over spilled tea, but--
[sniffles]
--it's just so sad!
- [violin plays]
- [drill whirring]
- Wow, it looks
a lot thicker in person
than it does in the plans.
We're gonna have to work pretty
hard to cut through that.
- What's this "we" stuff?
Aang and I are gonna
have to do all the work.
- Look, I'm the plan guy.
You two are the cut stuff
up with waterbending guys.
Together, we're Team Avatar.
- [water sloshing]
- [dinging]
- ♪
- [panting]
- Come on, team!
Don't quit now!
- We're--
- [growls in frustration]
- I mean, you're almost there!
- [dinging]
- MOMA: [chatters]
- [creaking]
- [sighs]
At this rate,
we won't do enough damage
before the drill
reaches the wall.
- I don't know how many
more of those I have in me.
- [creaking]
- [rumbling]
- Do you hear that?
We took it down!
We better get out of here fast.
- QIN (ON PA):
Congratulations, crew!
The drill has made contact
with the wall of Ba Sing Se.
Start the countdown to victory!
- CREW: [cheering]
- [drill whirring]
- [grunts]
Come on, brace!
Budge!
[grunts]
- This is bad.
Really bad.
- [pants]
We're putting everything we've
got into busting these braces,
but it's taking too long!
- Maybe we don't need to
cut all the way through.
Toph has been teaching me
that you shouldn't give 100% of
your energy into any one strike.
Sokka, take a fighting stance.
You've gotta be
quick and accurate.
Hit a series of points and
break your opponent's stance.
And when he's reeling back,
you deliver the final blow.
His own weight becomes
his downfall, literally.
- So we just need
to weaken the braces
instead of cutting
all the way through.
- Then I'll go
to the top of this thing
and deliver the final blow.
- And boom, it all
comes crashing down!
- Everyone inside that wall, the
whole world, is counting on us.
- The whole world minus
the Fire Nation, that is.
- [grunts]
Come on, Twinkle Toes!
Hurry up!
- [dinging]
- ♪
- That's enough!
We need to get to the next one.
- MAN (ON PA): War Minister!
An engineer was ambushed.
His schematics were stolen.
- MAN (ON PA): War Minister!
A brace on the starboard side
has been cut clean through!
It's sabotage, sir!
- Let's go, ladies.
- [water sloshing]
- [dinging]
- Good work, Team Avatar.
Now Aang just needs to--
duck!
- [blasts]
- Whoa!
- Wow, Azula, you were right!
It is the Avatar...
...and friends.
- Hey.
Aah!
- Whoa!
- MOMO: [chatters]
- Guys, get out of here!
I know what I need to do.
- Wait, you need this
water more than I do.
- [adventurous music]
♪
- Follow them.
The Avatar's mine.
- Slurry pipeline?
- [grunts]
- What does that mean?
It's rock and water
mixed together.
It means our way out.
- [pants]
- [splash]
- [screaming]
- Ugh, disgusting.
- Come on, you heard Azula.
We have to follow them.
- She can shoot all the
lightning she wants at me.
I am not going in that
wall sludge juice.
- [sighs]
- [splash]
- Ugh.
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [screaming]
- Ugh!
- [screams]
[moans]
[whimpers]
- Why don't you try blocking
my qi now, circus freak?
- Katara, keep that up.
The pressure will
build up in the drill.
Then, when Aang
delivers the final blow,
it'll be ready to pop!
- [clacking]
- MOMO: [chatters]
- This looks like
a good spot, Momo.
[grunts]
General Sung,
tell your soldiers
to stop shooting rocks
down here!
- Soldiers, whatever you do,
don't stop shooting rocks
down there!
- [crashing]
- [dinging]
- ♪
- Good technique, Little Sister.
Keep it up!
Don't forget to breathe.
- You know, I am just about
sick and tired
of you telling me what to do
all day.
You're like a
chattering hog monkey.
- Just bend the slurry, woman!
[screams]
- TOPH: You guys need some help?
- Toph, help me
plug up this drain.
- [splash]
- [creaking]
- [dinging]
- [pants]
What I'd give
to be a Metalbender.
- [squeals]
- Momo, get out of here!
- [chatters]
- [ominous music]
♪
- [blast]
- [water sloshing]
- [adventurous music]
♪
- Aah!
- [clank]
- [gasps]
- [blast]
- [clacking]
- [grunts]
[grunts]
- [thud]
- [grunts]
- [whoosh]
- [creaking]
- [rumbling]
- ♪
- [whimpers]
- [grunts]
- ♪
- Whoa!
Aah!
[pants]
[grunts]
- [splashing]
- [clacking]
- [chatters]
- [grunts]
- Thanks, Momo.
I owe you one.
- ♪
- Now all I need is a--
- [crash]
- Actually, that is
what I needed, for once.
- MOMO: [chatters]
- [clacking]
- ♪
- [whoosh]
- Aah!
- ♪
Aah!
- [creaking]
- [splashing]
- Woo-hoo!
- Here it comes!
- ♪
- Whoa!
- [creaking]
- [drill powers down]
- ♪
- [chatters]
- [sputters]
Ugh!
- [splash]
- We lost.
- MAN: Last call for Ba Sing Se!
- Jet, relax.
So the old guy had some hot tea.
Big deal!
- He heated it himself.
Those guys are Firebenders.
- What a handsome baby.
- Thank you.
- [gentle music]
♪
- [scraping]
- ♪
- SOKKA: I just wanted to say
good effort out there today,
Team Avatar.
- Enough with the
Team Avatar stuff.
No matter how many times you
say it, it's not gonna catch on.
- How about the Boomerang Squad?
See, it's good 'cause
it's got "ang" in it.
Boomer-Aang!
- I kinda like that one.
- Let's talk about this
on our way into the city.
- The Aang Gang?
- KATARA: Sokka.
- The Fearsome Foursome!
- TOPH: You're crazy.
- Why?
We're fearsome!
♪