Girl: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR:
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH
HIS AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Girl: APPA IS MISSING.
WE HOPE TO FIND HIM
IN BA SING SE.
PROFESSOR ZEI,
HEAD OF ANTHROPOLOGY
AT BA SING SE UNIVERSITY.
THIS LIBRARY IS SAID TO CONTAIN
A VAST COLLECTION OF KNOWLEDGE.
Boy: FIREBENDERS LOSE THEIR
BENDING DURING A SOLAR ECLIPSE!
WE'VE GOTTA GET THIS
INFORMATION TO THE EARTH KING
AT BA SING SE.
HEY!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
FIREBENDING YOUR TEA?
SO THE OLD GUY
HAD SOME HOT TEA, BIG DEAL.
HE HEATED IT HIMSELF.
THOSE GUYS ARE FIREBENDERS.
♪
LOOK, THE INNER WALL.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE FINALLY MADE IT
TO BA SING SE IN ONE PIECE.
HEY, DON'T JINX IT!
WE COULD STILL BE ATTACKED
BY SOME GIANT, EXPLODING
FIRE NATION SPOON.
OR FIND OUT THE CITY'S
BEEN SUBMERGED IN AN OCEAN
FULL OF KILLER SHRIMP.
YOU BEEN HITTING
THE CACTUS JUICE AGAIN?
I'M JUST SAYIN'.
WEIRD STUFF HAPPENS TO US.
[SUCKING]
DON'T WORRY, AANG,
WE'LL FIND APPA.
IT'S SUCH A BIG CITY.
HE'S A GIANT BISON.
WHERE COULD SOMEONE
POSSIBLY HIDE HIM?
OH.
Girl: AH, BACK IN THE CITY.
GREAT.
Boy: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
IT'S AMAZING!
JUST A BUNCH OF WALLS AND RULES.
YOU WAIT, YOU'LL GET SICK OF IT
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
Aang: I'M COMIN' FOR YOU, BUDDY.
HE'S HERE, I CAN FEEL IT.
HELLO, MY NAME IS JOO DEE.
I HAVE BEEN GIVEN
THE GREAT HONOR OF SHOWING
THE AVATAR AROUND BA SING SE.
AND YOU MUST BE SOKKA,
KATARA AND TOPH.
WELCOME TO OUR WONDERFUL CITY.
SHALL WE GET STARTED?
YES, WE HAVE INFORMATION ABOUT
THE FIRE NATION ARMY THAT
WE NEED TO DELIVER TO
THE EARTH KING IMMEDIATELY.
GREAT, LET'S BEGIN OUR TOUR.
AND THEN I'LL SHOW YOU
TO YOUR NEW HOME, HERE.
I THINK YOU'LL LIKE IT.
AUGH!
MAYBE YOU MISSED WHAT I SAID.
WE NEED TO TALK TO THE KING
ABOUT THE WAR,
IT'S IMPORTANT.
YOU'RE IN BA SING SE, NOW.
EVERYONE IS SAFE HERE.
Joo Dee: THIS IS THE LOWER RING.
WHAT'S THAT WALL FOR?
OH, BA SING SE HAS MANY WALLS.
THERE ARE THE ONES OUTSIDE,
PROTECTING US,
AND THE ONES INSIDE,
THAT HELP MAINTAIN ORDER.
THIS IS WHERE
OUR NEWEST ARRIVALS LIVE,
AS WELL AS OUR CRAFTSMEN
AND ARTISANS, PEOPLE THAT WORK
WITH THEIR HANDS.
IT'S SO QUAINT AND LIVELY.
YOU DO WANT TO
WATCH YOUR STEP, THOUGH.
WHY DO THEY HAVE ALL THESE
POOR PEOPLE BLOCKED OFF
IN ONE PART OF THE CITY?
THIS IS WHY
I NEVER CAME HERE BEFORE.
I ALWAYS HEARD IT WAS
SO DIFFERENT FROM THE WAY
THE MONKS TAUGHT US TO LIVE.
I JUST WANT OUR NEW PLACE
TO LOOK NICE IN CASE SOMEONE
BRINGS HOME A LADY FRIEND.
THIS CITY IS A PRISON.
I DON'T WANT TO
MAKE A LIFE HERE.
Old Man: LIFE HAPPENS
WHEREVER YOU ARE,
WHETHER YOU MAKE IT OR NOT.
NOW COME ON,
I FOUND US SOME NEW JOBS,
AND WE START THIS AFTERNOON.
LOOK AT THEM,
FIREBENDERS LIVING
RIGHT UNDER EVERYONE'S NOSE.
Girl: JET, YOU SAW A MAN
WITH A HOT CUP OF TEA.
IT DOESN'T PROVE
HE'S A FIREBENDER.
AND WHAT IF HE IS,
ARE WE SUPPOSED TO ATTACK THEM?
I THOUGHT WE WERE STARTING OVER
HERE, CHANGING OUR WAYS.
WE ARE, WHEN I GET THE EVIDENCE
I NEED, I'LL REPORT THEM
TO THE POLICE AND LET THEM
HANDLE IT, O.K.?
Joo Dee: THIS IS THE MIDDLE RING
OF BA SING SE,
HOME TO THE FINANCIAL DISTRICT,
SHOPS AND RESTAURANTS
AND THE UNIVERSITY.
YEAH, WE MET A PROFESSOR
FROM BA SING SE UNIVERSITY.
HE TOOK US TO
AN ANCIENT UNDERGROUND LIBRARY
WHERE WE DISCOVERED INFORMATION
ABOUT THE WAR
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY CRUCIAL
FOR THE KING TO HEAR !
ISN'T HISTORY FASCINATING?
LOOK, HERE'S ONE OF
THE OLDEST BUILDINGS
IN THE MIDDLE RING, TOWN HALL.
IS THAT WOMAN DEAF?
SHE ONLY SEEMS TO HEAR
EVERY OTHER WORD I SAY.
IT'S CALLED BEING HANDLED.
GET USED TO IT.
WELL, YOU CERTAINLY LOOK LIKE
OFFICIAL TEA SERVERS.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
RIDICULOUS.
UH, DOES THIS POSSIBLY COME IN
A LARGER SIZE?
I HAVE EXTRA STRING IN THE BACK.
HAVE SOME TEA WHILE YOU WAIT.
EOW!
THIS TEA IS NOTHING MORE
THAN HOT LEAF JUICE!
UNCLE, THAT'S WHAT ALL TEA IS.
HOW COULD A MEMBER OF
MY OWN FAMILY SAY SOMETHING
SO HORRIBLE?
WE'LL HAVE TO MAKE SOME
MAJOR CHANGES AROUND HERE.
[GASPING]
Joo Dee: THE UPPER RING IS HOME
TO OUR MOST IMPORTANT CITIZENS.
YOUR HOUSE
IS NOT TOO FAR FROM HERE.
WHAT'S INSIDE THAT WALL?
AND WHO ARE
THE MEAN-LOOKING GUYS IN ROBES?
INSIDE IS THE ROYAL PALACE.
THOSE MEN ARE AGENTS OF
THE DAI LI, THE CULTURAL
AUTHORITY OF BA SING SE.
THEY ARE THE GUARDIANS
OF ALL OUR TRADITIONS.
CAN WE SEE THE KING NOW?
[LAUGHING] OH, NO!
ONE DOESN'T JUST POP IN
ON THE EARTH KING.
Joo Dee: HERE WE ARE,
YOUR NEW HOME.
MORE GOOD NEWS.
YOUR REQUEST FOR AN AUDIENCE
WITH THE EARTH KING
IS BEING PROCESSED,
AND SHOULD BE PUT THROUGH
IN ABOUT A MONTH.
MUCH MORE QUICKLY THAN USUAL.
A MONTH?
SIX TO EIGHT WEEKS, ACTUALLY.
Joo Dee: ISN'T IT NICE?
I THINK
YOU'LL REALLY ENJOY IT HERE.
I THINK WE'D ENJOY IT MORE
IF WE WEREN'T STAYING SO LONG.
CAN'T WE SEE THE KING
ANY SOONER?
THE EARTH KING IS VERY BUSY
RUNNING THE FINEST CITY
IN THE WORLD,
BUT HE WILL SEE YOU
AS SOON AS TIME PERMITS.
IF WE'RE GONNA BE HERE
FOR A MONTH, WE SHOULD
SPEND OUR TIME LOOKING FOR APPA.
I'LL BE HAPPY TO ESCORT YOU
ANYWHERE YOU'D LIKE TO GO.
WE DON'T NEED A BABYSITTER.
OH, I WON'T GET IN THE WAY.
AND TO LEAVE YOU ALONE
WOULD MAKE ME A BAD HOST.
WHERE SHALL WE START?
[CHIRPING]
[SCREECHING]
I'M SORRY, BUT I HAVEN'T HEARD
ANYTHING ABOUT A FLYING BISON.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THERE WERE ANY.
IF SOMEONE WANTED TO SELL
A STOLEN ANIMAL WITHOUT ANYONE
KNOWING, WHERE WOULD THEY GO?
WHERE'S THE BLACK MARKET?
WHO RUNS IT?
COME ON, YOU KNOW.
UH...
THAT WOULD BE ILLEGAL.
YOU'LL HAVE TO LEAVE NOW.
YOUR LEMUR IS HARASSING
MY SPARROWKEETS.
Boy: HMM, I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANY SANDBENDERS OR NOMADS
AROUND HERE.
YOU SHOULD ASK PROFESSOR ZEI,
HE TEACHES THE CLASS
ON DESERT CULTURES.
RIGHT.
AND WHICH OF YOUR PROFESSORS
COULD WE ASK ABOUT THE WAR
WITH THE FIRE NATION?
I DON'T KNOW, I'M NOT
A POLITICAL SCIENCE STUDENT,
I HAVE TO GET TO CLASS.
UNH!
Joo Dee: WELL, I'M SORRY NO ONE
HAS SEEN YOUR BISON.
WHY DON'T YOU GO GET SOME REST?
SOMEONE WILL BE OVER
WITH DINNER LATER.
HEY, COME WITH ME.
YOU'RE THE AVATAR.
I HEARD YOU WERE IN TOWN.
I'M PONG.
NICE TO MEET YOU, PONG.
SO, PONG, WHAT'S GOIN' ON
WITH THIS CITY?
WHY IS EVERYONE HERE
SO SCARED TO TALK ABOUT THE WAR?
WAR, SCARED?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I CAN FEEL YOU SHAKING.
LOOK, I'M JUST
A MINOR GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL.
I'VE WAITED THREE YEARS
TO GET THIS HOUSE.
I DON'T WANT TO
GET INTO TROUBLE.
GET IN TROUBLE WITH WHO?
SHH, LISTEN, YOU CAN'T
MENTION THE WAR, HERE.
AND WHATEVER YOU DO,
STAY AWAY FROM THE DAI LI.
Old Man: WOULD YOU LIKE
A POT OF TEA?
Young Man: WE'VE BEEN WORKING
IN A TEA SHOP ALL DAY.
I'M SICK OF TEA.
SICK OF TEA?
THAT'S LIKE BEING
SICK OF BREATHING.
HAVE YOU SEEN OUR SPARK ROCKS
TO HEAT UP THE WATER?
THEY'RE NOT THERE.
YOU'LL HAVE TO FIREBEND,
OLD MAN.
Jet: WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
Old Man: I BORROWED
OUR NEIGHBOR'S.
SUCH KIND PEOPLE.
[CHIRPING]
[YAWNING]
[GASPING]
I'VE GOT IT!
I KNOW HOW
WE'RE GONNA SEE THE EARTH KING.
HOW'RE WE SUPPOSED TO DO THAT?
"ONE DOESN'T JUST POP IN
ON THE EARTH KING."
THE KING IS HAVING A PARTY
AT THE PALACE TONIGHT
FOR HIS PET BEAR.
YOU MEAN PLATYPUS-BEAR?
NO, IT JUST SAYS "BEAR."
CERTAINLY YOU MEAN
HIS PET SKUNK-BEAR.
OR HIS ARMADILLO-BEAR.
GOPHER-BEAR?
JUST "BEAR."
THIS PLACE IS WEIRD .
THE PALACE WILL BE PACKED.
WE CAN SNEAK IN WITH A CROWD.
WON'T WORK.
WHY NOT?
WELL, NO OFFENSE
TO YOU SIMPLE COUNTRY FOLK,
BUT A REAL SOCIETY CROWD
WOULD SPOT YOU A MILE AWAY.
YOU'VE GOT NO MANNERS.
EXCUSE ME?
I'VE GOT NO MANNERS?
YOU'RE NOT EXACTLY
LADY FANCY FINGERS.
Toph: [BURPING]
I LEARNED PROPER SOCIETY
BEHAVIOR AND CHOSE TO LEAVE IT.
YOU NEVER LEARNED ANYTHING.
AND FRANKLY,
IT'S A LITTLE TOO LATE.
AH-HA, BUT YOU LEARNED IT!
YOU COULD TEACH US.
YEAH, I'M MASTERING
EVERY ELEMENT.
HOW HARD CAN MANNERS BE?
"GOOD EVENING,
MR. SOKKA WATER TRIBE.
MISS KATARA WATER TRIBE.
LORD MOMO OF THE MOMO DYNASTY,
YOUR MOMO-NESS."
"AVATAR AANG, HOW YOU DO GO ON."
Aang: OW!
KATARA MIGHT BE ABLE TO
PULL IT OFF,
BUT YOU TWO WOULD BE LUCKY
TO PASS AS BUSBOYS.
BUT I FEEL SO FANCY.
Aang: EARTH!
Sokka: FIRE!
AUGH.
OOH.
[GIGGLING]
WOW, YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL.
DON'T TALK TO
THE COMMONERS, KATARA.
FIRST RULE OF SOCIETY.
WE'LL GET IN THE PARTY
AND THEN FIND A WAY TO LET YOU
IN THROUGH THE SIDE GATE.
[GONG RINGING]
Girl: JET, WE NEED TO TALK.
WHAT?
OH, GREAT, IT'S YOU GUYS.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
I COULD USE SOME HELP
WITH SURVEILLANCE HERE.
Girl: WE'VE BEEN TALKING,
AND WE THINK YOU'RE BECOMING
OBSESSED WITH THIS.
IT'S NOT HEALTHY.
OH, REALLY?
YOU BOTH THINK THIS?
WE CAME HERE
TO MAKE A FRESH START.
BUT YOU WON'T LET THIS GO.
EVEN THOUGH
THERE'S NO REAL PROOF!
WELL, MAYBE IF YOU'D HELP ME.
JET, YOU'VE GOTTA STOP THIS.
MAYBE YOU'VE FORGOTTEN WHY WE
NEED TO START OVER.
MAYBE YOU'VE FORGOTTEN
ABOUT HOW THE FIRE NATION
LEFT US ALL HOMELESS?
HOW THEY WIPED OUT
ALL THE PEOPLE WE LOVED?
IF YOU DON'T WANNA HELP ME,
I'LL GET THE EVIDENCE ON MY OWN.
THIS IS THE BEST TEA
IN THE CITY.
THE SECRET INGREDIENT IS LOVE.
I THINK YOU'RE DUE FOR A RAISE.
I'M TIRED OF WAITING.
THESE TWO MEN ARE FIREBENDERS!
I KNOW THEY'RE FIREBENDERS!
I SAW THE OLD MAN
HEATING HIS TEA.
HE WORKS IN A TEA SHOP.
HE'S A FIREBENDER,
I'M TELLING YOU!
DROP YOUR SWORDS, BOY,
NICE AND EASY.
YOU'LL HAVE TO DEFEND YOURSELF.
THEN EVERYONE WILL KNOW.
GO AHEAD, SHOW THEM
WHAT YOU CAN DO.
YOU WANT A SHOW?
I'LL GIVE YOU A SHOW.
Man: INVITATION, PLEASE.
I THINK THIS WILL DO.
NO ENTRY WITHOUT AN INVITATION.
STEP OUT OF LINE, PLEASE.
LOOK, THE PANGS
AND THE YUMSOON-HANS
ARE WAITING IN THERE FOR US.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TELL THEM WHO DIDN'T LET ME IN.
STEP OUT OF LINE, PLEASE.
Katara: SIR?
I'M SORRY TO BOTHER YOU, BUT MY
COUSIN LOST OUR INVITATIONS.
[WHISPERING] SHE'S BLIND.
DO YOU THINK YOU COULD HELP US?
OUR FAMILY'S INSIDE, AND
I'M SURE THEY'RE VERY WORRIED.
I AM HONORED.
PLEASE COME WITH ME.
NYAA.
[BLOWING RASPBERRY]
HE'S TAKING ALL THE GOOD STUFF.
QUIET, YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT I HAD TO DO TO GET SEATS
THIS NEAR THE BEAR.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL, ISN'T IT?
BY THE WAY, I'M LONG FENG.
I'M A CULTURAL MINISTER
TO THE KING.
I'M HWAMEI, AND THIS IS DUNG.
OW!
NOW WHERE IS YOUR FAMILY?
I'D LOVE TO MEET THEM.
UH, I DON'T SEE 'EM RIGHT NOW,
BUT I'M SURE
WE'LL FIND THEM SOON.
THANKS FOR ALL YOUR HELP.
DON'T WORRY, AS YOUR ESCORT,
IT WOULD BE DISHONORABLE
TO ABANDON YOU LADIES WITHOUT
FINDING YOUR FAMILY, FIRST.
WE'LL KEEP LOOKING.
WHERE ARE THEY?
LOOK, I CAME UP
WITH A BACK-UP PLAN.
WE DRESS MOMO
LIKE A GHOST, O.K.?
HE FLIES BY THE GUARDS,
CREATING A DISTRACTION.
THEN WE BLAST A HOLE
IN THE WALL...
OR WE CAN GO IN WITH THESE GUYS.
Aang: TOPH SAID
WE MIGHT PASS AS BUSBOYS.
O.K., BUT REMEMBER
THAT MOMO GHOST PLAN.
I THINK IT'S A WINNER.
UGH!
[GRUNTING]
YOU MUST BE GETTING TIRED OF
USING THOSE SWORDS.
WHY DON'T YOU GO AHEAD
AND FIREBEND AT ME?
PLEASE, SON, YOU'RE CONFUSED!
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING!
Jet: BET YOU WISH HE HELPED YOU
OUT WITH A LITTLE FIRE BLAST
RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO NEEDS HELP.
YOU SEE THAT?
THE FIRE NATION
IS TRYING TO SILENCE ME!
IT'LL NEVER HAPPEN.
[GRUNTING]
WHERE ARE TOPH AND KATARA?
FORGET ABOUT THEM, JUST KEEP
AN EYE OUT FOR THE KING.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE LOOKS LIKE.
YOU KNOW, ROYAL,
FLOWING ROBE, FANCY JEWELRY.
Aang: THAT COULD BE ANYONE.
ANOTHER CRAB PUFF, PLEASE.
YOU FOUND US!
I'D KNOW YOUR LITTLE FOOTSTEPS
ANYWHERE, TWINKLE TOES.
THANKS FOR LETTING US IN.
SORRY, BUT THE GUY
WHO ESCORTED US IN
WON'T LET US OUT OF HIS SIGHT.
WHAT GUY?
Joo Dee: WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
YOU HAVE TO LEAVE IMMEDIATELY,
OR WE'LL ALL BE
IN TERRIBLE TROUBLE.
NOT UNTIL WE SEE THE KING.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU MUST GO.
Woman: [SCREAMING]
OH!
Aang: SORRY, NO, DON'T SHOUT.
THE AVATAR.
OH, I DIDN'T KNOW
THE AVATAR WOULD BE HERE.
[LAUGHING WEAKLY]
YOU KEEP THEIR ATTENTION
WHILE I LOOK FOR THE KING.
WATCH THIS, EVERYBODY.
Crowd: OOH...
[APPLAUSE]
[LAUGHING/GROWLING]
[GRUNTING]
DROP YOUR WEAPONS.
ARREST THEM,
THEY'RE FIREBENDERS.
THIS POOR BOY IS CONFUSED.
WE'RE JUST SIMPLE REFUGEES.
THIS YOUNG MAN
WRECKED MY TEA SHOP
AND ASSAULTED MY EMPLOYEES!
IT'S TRUE, SIR.
WE SAW THE WHOLE THING.
THIS CRAZY KID
ATTACKED THE FINEST TEA MAKER
IN THE CITY.
OH, THAT'S VERY SWEET.
COME WITH US, SON.
[GRUNTING]
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND!
THEY'RE FIRE NATION!
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME.
AANG, THE EARTH KING.
GREETINGS, YOUR MAJESTY.
[GASPING]
AUGH, UGH, LET ME GO!
[MUFFLED SHOUT]
[CHIRPING]
AVATAR, IT IS A GREAT HONOR
TO MEET YOU.
I AM LONG FENG,
GRAND SECRETARIAT OF BA SING SE
AND HEAD OF THE DAI LI.
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU.
YOUR FRIENDS WILL BE
WAITING FOR US IN THE LIBRARY.
Sokka: WHY WON'T YOU LET US
TALK TO THE KING?
WE HAVE INFORMATION THAT COULD
DEFEAT THE FIRE NATION!
Long Feng: THE EARTH KING
HAS NO TIME TO GET INVOLVED
WITH POLITICAL SQUABBLES
AND THE DAY-TO-DAY MINUTIA
OF MILITARY ACTIVITIES.
Aang: THIS COULD BE THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING HE'S EVER HEARD.
WHAT'S MOST IMPORTANT TO HIS
ROYAL MAJESTY IS MAINTAINING THE
CULTURAL HERITAGE OF BA SING SE.
ALL HIS DUTIES RELATE TO
ISSUING DECREES ON SUCH MATTERS.
IT'S MY JOB TO OVERSEE THE REST
OF THE CITY'S RESOURCES,
INCLUDING THE MILITARY.
SO THE KING
IS JUST A FIGUREHEAD.
HE'S YOUR PUPPET.
OH, NO, NO.
HIS MAJESTY IS AN ICON,
A GOD TO HIS PEOPLE.
HE CAN'T SULLY HIS HANDS
WITH THE HOURLY CHANGES
OF AN ENDLESS WAR.
BUT WE FOUND OUT ABOUT
A SOLAR ECLIPSE THAT WILL LEAVE
THE FIRE NATION DEFENSELESS.
YOU COULD LEAD AN INVASION...
ENOUGH, I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
YOUR RIDICULOUS PLAN.
IT IS THE STRICT POLICY
OF BA SING SE THAT THE WAR NOT
BE MENTIONED WITHIN THE WALLS.
CONSTANT NEWS OF
AN ESCALATING WAR WILL THROW
THE CITIZENS OF BA SING SE
INTO A STATE OF PANIC.
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME,
THEY'RE FIREBENDERS.
THEY WON'T STOP
UNTIL THEY WIN THE WAR.
CALM DOWN, YOU'RE SAFE NOW.
OUR ECONOMY WOULD BE RUINED,
OUR PEACEFUL WAY OF LIFE,
OUR TRADITIONS WOULD DISAPPEAR.
THERE'S NO WAR IN BA SING SE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHERE DO YOU THINK
ALL THE REFUGEES COME FROM?
YOU CAN'T HIDE IT.
IN SILENCING TALK OF CONFLICT,
BA SING SE REMAINS
A PEACEFUL, ORDERLY UTOPIA.
THE LAST ONE ON EARTH.
[MUFFLED GRUNTING]
THERE IS NO WAR
WITHIN THE WALLS.
HERE WE ARE SAFE.
HERE WE ARE FREE.
YOU CAN'T KEEP THE TRUTH
FROM ALL THESE PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE TO KNOW.
I'LL TELL THEM.
I'LL MAKE SURE EVERYONE KNOWS.
UNTIL NOW, YOU'VE BEEN TREATED
AS OUR HONORED GUEST.
BUT FROM NOW ON, YOU WILL BE
WATCHED EVERY MOMENT
BY DAI LI AGENTS.
IF YOU MENTION THE WAR
TO ANYONE, YOU WILL BE EXPELLED
FROM THE CITY.
I UNDERSTAND YOU'VE BEEN
LOOKING FOR YOUR BISON.
IT WOULD BE QUITE A SHAME
IF YOU WERE NOT ABLE
TO COMPLETE YOUR QUEST.
NOW JOO DEE WILL SHOW YOU HOME.
Woman: COME WITH ME, PLEASE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO JOO DEE?
I'M JOO DEE.
I'LL BE YOUR HOST AS LONG
AS YOU'RE IN OUR WONDERFUL CITY.
♪