Girl: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Girl: I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE FINALLY MADE IT TO
BA SING SE IN ONE PIECE.
I JUST WANT OUR NEW PLACE
TO LOOK NICE, IN CASE SOMEONE
BRINGS HOME A LADY FRIEND.
Young Man: I DON'T WANT TO
MAKE A LIFE HERE.
Woman: HERE WE ARE,
YOUR NEW HOME.
WE NEED TO TALK TO THE KING
ABOUT THE WAR.
YOUR REQUEST FOR AN AUDIENCE
WITH THE EARTH KING
IS BEING PROCESSED,
AND SHOULD BE PUT THROUGH
IN ABOUT A MONTH!
IF WE'RE GONNA BE HERE
FOR A MONTH, WE SHOULD
SPEND OUR TIME LOOKING FOR APPA.
♪
[CLICKING TONGUE]
[CHIRPING]
[GASPING]
TOPH, AREN'T YOU
GONNA GET READY FOR THE DAY?
[HOCKING AND SPITTING PHLEGM]
I'M READY.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA WASH UP?
YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE DIRT
ON YOUR... EVERYWHERE, ACTUALLY.
YOU CALL IT DIRT, I CALL IT
A HEALTHY COATING OF EARTH.
HMM...
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED?
A GIRLS DAY OUT!
DO I HAVE TO?
Katara: IT'LL BE FUN.
Toph: THE FANCY LADY DAY SPA?
SOUNDS LIKE MY KIND OF PLACE.
ARE YOU READY FOR
SOME SERIOUS PAMPERING?
[HESITATINGLY]: SURE, KATARA.
WHATEVER YOU SAY.
AS LONG AS
THEY DON'T TOUCH MY FEET.
[SCRAPING]
[GRUNTING AND GROWLING]
UGH!
UH...
[BLOWING]
[SCREAMING]
[LAUGHING]
[SIGHING]
WELL, THAT WASN'T SO BAD.
I'M NOT USUALLY
INTO THAT STUFF,
BUT I ACTUALLY FEEL... GIRLY.
Katara: I'M GLAD.
IT'S ABOUT TIME
WE DID SOMETHING FUN TOGETHER.
WOW, GREAT MAKEUP.
THANKS.
FOR A CLOWN.
[LAUGHING]
DON'T LISTEN TO THEM.
LET'S JUST KEEP WALKING.
I THINK SHE LOOKS CUTE.
LIKE THAT TIME WE PUT A SWEATER
ON YOUR PET POODLE-MONKEY.
[LAUGHTER]
Girl: GOOD ONE, STAR.
LET'S GO, TOPH.
Toph: NO, NO,
THAT WAS A GOOD ONE.
"LIKE YOUR POODLE-MONKEY."
[LAUGHING]
YOU, YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE
IS A GOOD ONE?
[SCREAMING]
NOW THAT WAS FUNNY.
THOSE GIRLS DON'T KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT.
Toph: IT'S O.K.
ONE OF THE GOOD THINGS
ABOUT BEING BLIND
IS THAT I DON'T HAVE TO
WASTE MY TIME
WORRYING ABOUT APPEARANCES.
I DON'T CARE WHAT I LOOK LIKE.
I'M NOT LOOKING FOR
ANYONE'S APPROVAL.
I KNOW WHO I AM.
Katara: THAT'S WHAT
I REALLY ADMIRE ABOUT YOU, TOPH.
YOU'RE SO STRONG AND CONFIDENT
AND SELF-ASSURED.
[SNIFFING]
AND I KNOW
IT DOESN'T MATTER, BUT...
YOU'RE REALLY PRETTY.
I AM?
YEAH, YOU ARE.
Toph: I'D RETURN
THE COMPLIMENT, BUT I HAVE
NO IDEA WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE.
Katara: [LAUGHING]
Toph: THANK YOU, KATARA.
Katara: OW!
IF THIS IS FOR
A ROMANTIC PICNIC,
MAY I SUGGEST THIS LAVENDER ONE?
NO, IT'S NOT A ROMANTIC PICNIC,
BUT IT IS A SPECIAL OCCASION.
Iroh: THE MOONFLOWER
LIKES PARTIAL SHADE.
Child: [CRYING]
Woman: IT'S O.K.,
SHH, SHH, SHH.
Woman: IT'S O.K., SHH.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ LEAVES FROM THE VINE ♪
♪ FALLING SO SLOW ♪
♪ LIKE FRAGILE, TINY SHELLS
DRIFTING IN THE FOAM ♪
♪ LITTLE SOLDIER BOY,
COME MARCHING HOME ♪
♪ BRAVE SOLDIER BOY ♪
♪ COMES MARCHING HOME ♪
YEOWCH!
[LAUGHING]
Man: HEY!
Iroh: IT IS USUALLY BEST TO
ADMIT MISTAKES WHEN THEY OCCUR.
AND TO SEEK TO RESTORE HONOR.
[STOMPING]
WHEN I'M THROUGH WITH YOU KIDS,
THE WINDOW WON'T BE
THE ONLY THING THAT'S BROKEN!
BUT NOT THIS TIME.
RUN!
Man: YOU.
GIVE ME ALL YOUR MONEY!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M MUGGING YOU!
WITH THAT STANCE?
WHA-?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
JUST GIVE ME YOUR MONEY,
OLD MAN!
WITH A POOR STANCE,
YOU ARE UNBALANCED, AND YOU
CAN BE EASILY KNOCKED OVER.
UGH!
WITH A SOLID STANCE, YOU ARE
A MUCH MORE SERIOUS THREAT.
MUCH BETTER!
BUT TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
YOU DO NOT LOOK LIKE
THE CRIMINAL TYPE.
I KNOW, I'M...
I'M JUST CONFUSED.
Man: SO YOU REALLY THINK
I COULD BE A GOOD MASSEUR?
OF COURSE!
THIS IS SO GREAT!
NO ONE HAS EVER BELIEVED IN ME.
WHILE IT IS ALWAYS BEST
TO BELIEVE IN ONESELF,
A LITTLE HELP FROM OTHERS
CAN BE A GREAT BLESSING.
Iroh: HAPPY BIRTHDAY, MY SON.
IF ONLY I COULD HAVE HELPED YOU.
♪ LEAVES FROM THE VINE ♪
♪ FALLING SO SLOW ♪
♪ LIKE FRAGILE, TINY SHELLS
DRIFTING IN THE FOAM ♪
[CRYING]: ♪ LITTLE SOLDIER BOY ♪
♪ COME MARCHING HOME ♪
♪ BRAVE SOLDIER BOY ♪
♪ COMES MARCHING HOME ♪
[♪...]
HEY THERE, FELLA.
Aang: YOU LOOK HUNGRY.
AHH!
THEY ARE HUNGRY.
THE DAI LI WON'T GIVE ME
ANY MONEY BECAUSE THE KIDS
STOPPED COMING.
AND THE KIDS WON'T COME BECAUSE
MY ZOO'S NASTY AND BROKE.
WHAT KIND OF ANIMAL IS THAT?
OOH, THAT'S A RABBIROO.
I WISH I COULD GET HER A BIG,
OPEN PRAIRIE, LIKE SHE LIKES.
I'D LET HER
HOP HER WAY TO HAPPINESS.
LET'S DO IT.
SAY AGAIN?
THERE'S A BIG OPEN SPACE RIGHT
OUTSIDE THE WALLS OF THE CITY.
Man: BUT HOW ARE YOU
GONNA TRANSPORT ALL THESE
WILD CRITTERS?
DON'T WORRY,
I'M GREAT WITH ANIMALS.
[SCREAMING]
[SPUTTERING]
MY CAB-
OH, FORGET IT.
[SCREAMING]
THIS WAS SO MUCH EASIER
IN MY HEAD.
[INHALING]
[CRYING]
OOM-OOM-OOM, OOM-OOM-OOM.
BUT YOU HAVE TO OPEN THIS GATE!
OR WHAT?
OR THAT!
OPEN THE GATE!
[GRUNTING]
[LAUGHING]
[SQUEAKING]
WELL, MR. ZOOKEEPER, HOW DO YOU
LIKE YOUR NEW FACILITIES?
EXCELLENT JOB, AVATAR.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT WORKING
WITH ANIMALS FOR A LIVING.
Child: MOMMY, MISS SNOWFLAKE GOT
OUT OF THE HOUSE AGAIN.
[HISSING]
Child: FLUFFIKINS, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING DOWN THERE?
[MEOWING]
ON SECOND THOUGHT, YOU SHOULD
PROBABLY STICK TO SAVING PEOPLE.
[LAUGHING NERVOUSLY]
♪
Animal: [GRUNTING]
[FAINT CONVERSATION]
WHAT'S THIS?
"THROUGH ALL THE LONG NIGHT,
WINTER MOON GLOWS
WITH BRIGHT LOVE.
SLEET, HER SILVER TEARS."
AHH, POETRY.
[GRUNTING]
AUGH!
Women: [GASPING]
I AM SO SORRY.
SOMETHING STRUCK ME IN THE REAR.
I JUST... WOUND UP... HERE?
[LAUGHING]
"FIVE, SEVEN, THEN FIVE
SYLLABLES MARK A HAIKU,
REMARKABLE OAF."
"THEY CALL ME SOKKA,
THAT IS, IN THE WATER TRIBE,
I AM NOT AN OAF."
[LAUGHING]
"CHITTERING MONKEY,
IN THE SPRING HE CLIMBS TREETOPS
AND THINKS HIMSELF TALL."
OOH...
"YOU THINK YOU'RE SO SMART,
WITH YOUR FANCY, LITTLE WORDS.
THIS IS NOT SO HARD."
Women: OOH...
"WHOLE SEASONS ARE SPENT
MASTERING THE FORM, THE STYLE,
NONE CALLS IT EASY."
"I CALLS IT EASY.
LIKE I PADDLE MY CANOE,
I'LL PADDLE YOURS, TOO."
[LAUGHING]
"THERE'S NUTS AND THERE'S FRUITS
IN FALL, THE CLEAN PLUM DROPS,
ALWAYS TO BE SQUASHED."
"SQUISH-SQUASH SLING THAT SLANG,
I'M ALWAYS RIGHT BACK AT YA,
LIKE MY... BOOMERANG."
[LAUGHING]
"THAT'S RIGHT, I'M SOKKA,
IT'S PRONOUNCED WITH AN 'OKKA,'
YOUNG LADIES, I ROCKED YA."
[CRICKET CHIRPING]
UH, THAT'S ONE TOO MANY
SYLLABLES THERE, BUB.
AUGH!
POETRY.
[♪...]
UNCLE, WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
ONE OF THE CUSTOMERS
IS ON TO US.
DON'T LOOK NOW,
BUT THERE WAS A GIRL
OVER THERE AT THE CORNER TABLE.
Zuko: SHE KNOWS
WE'RE FIRE NATION.
DIDN'T I SAY DON'T LOOK?
Iroh: YOU'RE RIGHT, ZUKO.
I'VE SEEN THAT GIRL IN HERE
QUITE A LOT.
SEEMS TO ME SHE HAS
QUITE A LITTLE CRUSH ON YOU.
WHAT?
THANK YOU FOR THE TEA.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
MY NAME'S LEE.
MY UNCLE AND I JUST MOVED HERE.
HI, LEE, MY NAME'S JIN.
THANK YOU, AND, WELL,
I WAS WONDERING IF YOU WOULD
LIKE TO GO OUT SOME TIME.
HE'D LOVE TO.
GREAT!
I'LL MEET YOU IN FRONT OF
THE SHOP AT SUNDOWN.
HEY.
WELL, LOOK AT YOU.
YOU LOOK SO CUTE.
IT TOOK MY UNCLE
TEN MINUTES TO DO MY HAIR.
SO, HOW DO YOU
LIKE THE CITY SO FAR?
IT'S O.K.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE TO DO FOR FUN?
NOTHING.
EXCUSE ME, SIR,
WOULD YOU AND YOUR GIRLFRIEND
CARE FOR DESSERT?
[SCREAMING]: SHE IS NOT
MY GIRLFRIEND!
YOU HAVE...
QUITE AN APPETITE FOR A GIRL.
UM, THANKS?
SO, LEE, WHERE WERE YOU
AND YOUR UNCLE LIVING
BEFORE YOU CAME HERE?
[HESITATINGLY]: UM, WELL,
WE'VE BEEN TRAVELING AROUND
FOR A LONG TIME.
OH!
WHY WERE YOU TRAVELING SO MUCH?
WE WERE, UH, PART OF THIS
TRAVELING CIRCUS.
REALLY?
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WAIT, LET ME GUESS.
YOU JUGGLED.
YES, I JUGGLED.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO
LEARN HOW TO JUGGLE.
CAN YOU SHOW ME SOMETHING?
UH...
WHOA, UH!
I HAVEN'T PRACTICED FOR A WHILE.
Jin: IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HEY, I WANT TO SHOW YOU
ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES
IN THE CITY.
Jin: I'M SO EXCITED FOR YOU
TO SEE THE FIRELIGHT FOUNTAIN.
THE LAMPS MAKE THE WATER
SPARKLE, AND REFLECT IN THE POOL
IN THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WAY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT!
Jin: THEY AREN'T LIT.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
AND DON'T PEEK.
Zuko: O.K., NOW YOU CAN LOOK.
OH, WOW...
Jin: WHAT HAPPENED?
HOW DID THEY LIGHT?
WHAT DID YOU...
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
Zuko: IT'S A COUPON
FOR A FREE CUP OF TEA.
LEE, THIS IS SO SWEET.
DON'T THANK ME,
IT WAS MY UNCLE'S IDEA.
HE THINKS YOU'RE OUR
MOST VALUABLE CUSTOMER.
YOUR UNCLE IS A GOOD TEACHER.
I HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU, TOO.
NOW IT'S YOUR TURN
TO CLOSE YOUR EYES.
Jin: WHAT'S WRONG?
IT'S COMPLICATED.
I HAVE TO GO.
HOW WAS YOUR NIGHT, PRINCE ZUKO?
IT WAS NICE.
[♪...]
Appa: [GROWLING]
Momo: [CHIRPING]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[CHIRPING]
[ROARING]
[CHIRPING SADLY]
[GROWLING]
[SNARLING]
[MEOWING AND SNARLING]
[APPLAUSE]
[GROWLING AND SNARLING]
[GROWLING]
[ROARING]
[SPEAKING IN GIBBERISH]
[SNARLING AND MEOWING]
[PURRING AND CHIRPING]
[CHIRPING]
[RAIN FALLING]
♪