KATARA: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Boy: THE FIRE NATION
KILLED MY PARENTS.
I WAS ONLY EIGHT YEARS OLD.
HELLO, MY NAME IS JOO DEE.
WE FOUND OUT ABOUT
A SOLAR ECLIPSE THAT WILL LEAVE
THE FIRE NATION DEFENSELESS.
IT IS THE STRICT POLICY OF
BA SING SE THAT THE WAR NOT BE
MENTIONED WITHIN THE WALLS.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND,
THEY'RE FIRE NATION!
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ME.
THERE IS NO WAR
WITHIN THE WALLS.
HERE WE ARE SAFE.
HERE WE ARE FREE.
Man: I UNDERSTAND YOU'VE BEEN
LOOKING FOR YOUR BISON.
IT WOULD BE QUITE A SHAME
IF YOU WERE NOT ABLE TO
COMPLETE YOUR QUEST.
♪
WE FOUND A PRINTER
TO MAKE OUR POSTERS.
HEY, I THOUGHT DESIGNING THE
"LOST APPA" POSTER WAS MY JOB.
I'VE BEEN WORKING ALL DAY
ON MY APPA.
SOKKA, THE ARROW
[LAUGHING]
IS ON APPA'S HEAD .
THIS IS HIS HEAD.
WHY ARE FEET COMING OUT OF IT?
THOSE ARE HIS HORNS!
I HAVEN'T SEEN HIM
IN A WHILE, O.K.?
IT LOOKS JUST LIKE HIM TO ME.
THANK YOU, I WORKED REALLY...
WHY DO YOU FEEL
THE NEED TO DO THAT?
LET'S JUST STICK WITH
THE PROFESSIONAL VERSION.
[GROWLING]
COME ON, LET'S GET BUSY!
[♪...]
SO YOU'RE THE GENIUS
BEHIND THIS INCREDIBLE BREW.
THE WHOLE CITY
IS BUZZING ABOUT YOU!
I HOPE PAO PAYS YOU WELL.
GOOD TEA IS ITS OWN REWARD.
BUT IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE
THE ONLY REWARD.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO HAVE
YOUR OWN TEA SHOP?
MY OWN TEA SHOP?
THIS IS A DREAM COME TRUE.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
ARE YOU TRYING TO
POACH MY TEA MAKER?
SORRY, PAO, BUT THAT'S BUSINESS
FOR YOU, AM I RIGHT?
MUSHI, IF YOU STAY,
I'LL MAKE YOU ASSISTANT MANAGER.
WAIT, SENIOR ASSISTANT MANAGER.
I'LL PROVIDE YOU
WITH A NEW APARTMENT
IN THE UPPER RING.
THE TEA SHOP IS YOURS
TO DO WHATEVER YOU WANT,
COMPLETE CREATIVE FREEDOM.
I EVEN GET TO NAME THE SHOP?
OF COURSE!
UH, SENIOR EXECUTIVE
ASSISTANT MANAGER?
OOH.
DID YOU HEAR, NEPHEW?
THIS MAN WANTS TO GIVE US
OUR OWN TEA SHOP
IN THE UPPER RING OF THE CITY.
THAT'S RIGHT, YOUNG MAN.
YOUR LIFE IS ABOUT TO
CHANGE FOR THE BETTER.
Nephew: I'LL TRY TO
CONTAIN MY JOY.
I JUST FINISHED
DROPPING ALL THE LEAFLETS.
HAS ANYONE COME IN
WITH NEWS ABOUT APPA?
IT'S ONLY BEEN A DAY,
JUST BE PATIENT.
[KNOCKING]
WOW, YOU'RE RIGHT!
PATIENCE REALLY PAYS OFF.
JOO DEE?
HELLO, AANG AND KATARA
AND SOKKA AND TOPH.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
DID THE DAI LI
THROW YOU IN JAIL?
WHAT, JAIL?
OF COURSE NOT.
THE DAI LI ARE THE PROTECTORS
OF OUR CULTURAL HERITAGE.
BUT YOU DISAPPEARED
AT THE EARTH KING'S PARTY.
OH, I SIMPLY TOOK
A SHORT VACATION TO
LAKE LAOGAI, OUT IN THE COUNTRY.
IT WAS QUITE RELAXING.
BUT THEN THEY REPLACED YOU
WITH SOME OTHER WOMAN WHO ALSO
SAID HER NAME WAS JOO DEE.
I'M JOO DEE.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
DROPPING FLYERS AND PUTTING UP
POSTERS ISN'T PERMITTED WITHIN
THE CITY.
NOT WITHOUT PROPER CLEARANCE.
WE CAN'T WAIT AROUND TO GET
PERMISSION FOR EVERYTHING.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY FORBIDDEN
BY THE RULES OF THE CITY TO
CONTINUE PUTTING UP POSTERS.
WE DON'T CARE ABOUT THE RULES
AND WE'RE NOT ASKING PERMISSION!
WE'RE FINDING APPA ON OUR OWN
AND YOU SHOULD JUST
STAY OUT OF OUR WAY!
THAT MIGHT COME BACK
TO BITE US IN THE BLUBBER.
I DON'T CARE.
FROM NOW ON, WE DO
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO FIND APPA.
YEAH, LET'S BREAK SOME RULES!
I'M VERY DISAPPOINTED
IN YOUR WORK WITH THE AVATAR AND
HIS FRIENDS, JOO DEE.
I HAD HOPED THAT YOU WOULD BE
ABLE TO CONTROL THIS SITUATION.
I'M SO SORRY,
BUT THEY DON'T TRUST ME ANYMORE.
I DON'T THINK
I CAN KEEP WORKING LIKE THIS.
JOO DEE, THE EARTH KING HAS
INVITED YOU TO LAKE LAOGAI.
Joo Dee: I AM HONORED
TO ACCEPT HIS INVITATION.
GOOD.
NOW GO AWAIT FURTHER ORDERS.
IF THE AVATAR KEEPS SEARCHING
FOR HIS BISON,
IT COULD UPSET THE DELICATE
BALANCE WE'VE WORKED SO HARD
TO ACHIEVE IN THIS CITY.
IT COULD EVEN COST US CONTROL OF
THE EARTH KING.
SHOULD WE TAKE CARE OF HIM?
NO, IT'S MUCH TOO DANGEROUS FOR
US TO CONFRONT HIM DIRECTLY.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN STILL HANDLE
THIS... QUIETLY.
SO I WAS THINKING ABOUT NAMES
FOR MY NEW TEA SHOP.
HOW 'BOUT THE JASMINE DRAGON?
IT'S DRAMATIC, POETIC,
HAS A NICE RING TO IT.
THE AVATAR'S HERE IN BA SING SE.
AND HE'S LOST HIS BISON.
WE HAVE A CHANCE
FOR A NEW LIFE HERE.
IF YOU START STIRRING UP
TROUBLE, WE COULD LOSE
ALL THE GOOD THINGS
THAT ARE HAPPENING FOR US.
GOOD THINGS THAT ARE HAPPENING
FOR YOU .
HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT THAT
I WANT MORE FROM LIFE THAN A
NICE APARTMENT AND A JOB
SERVING TEA?
THERE IS NOTHING WRONG WITH
A LIFE OF PEACE AND PROSPERITY.
I SUGGEST YOU THINK ABOUT
WHAT IT IS THAT YOU WANT
FROM YOUR LIFE, AND WHY.
I WANT MY DESTINY.
WHAT THAT MEANS IS UP TO YOU.
THE TEA WEEVIL!
NO, THAT'S STUPID.
WE'LL SPLIT UP
TO COVER MORE AREA.
TOPH, I GUESS YOU SHOULD
JUST COME WITH ME.
WHY, BECAUSE YOU THINK I CAN'T
PUT UP POSTERS ON MY OWN?
Toph: IT'S UPSIDE-DOWN,
ISN'T IT?
I'LL JUST GO WITH SOKKA.
Voice: KATARA?
[GASPING]
I THINK I CAN HELP YOU.
[SCREAMING]
KATARA, I'VE CHANGED!
TELL IT TO SOME OTHER GIRL, JET.
[GROWLING]
[GRUNTING]
I DON'T WANT TO FIGHT YOU,
I'M HERE TO HELP.
[GRUNTING]
Sokka: KATARA, WHAT IS IT?
JET'S BACK.
WE CAN'T TRUST
ANYTHING JET SAYS.
BUT WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHY HE'S HERE.
I DON'T CARE WHY HE'S HERE.
WHATEVER THE REASON IS,
IT CAN'T BE GOOD.
I'M HERE TO HELP YOU FIND APPA.
KATARA, WE HAVE TO GIVE HIM
A CHANCE.
I SWEAR, I'VE CHANGED.
I WAS A TROUBLED PERSON,
AND I LET MY ANGER GET OUT
OF CONTROL.
BUT I DON'T EVEN HAVE
THE GANG, NOW.
I'VE PUT ALL THAT BEHIND ME.
YOU'RE LYING.
HE'S NOT LYING.
Sokka: HOW CAN YOU TELL?
Toph: I CAN FEEL HIS BREATHING
AND HEARTBEAT.
WHEN PEOPLE LIE,
THERE'S A PHYSICAL REACTION.
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
KATARA, WE DON'T HAVE ANY LEADS.
IF JET SAYS HE CAN TAKE US TO
APPA, WE HAVE TO CHECK IT OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
BUT WE'RE NOT LETTING YOU
OUT OF OUR SIGHT.
THIS IS THE PLACE I HEARD ABOUT.
THERE'S NOTHING HERE.
IF THIS IS A TRAP...
I TOLD YOU, I WORK NEARBY.
TWO GUYS WERE TALKIN' ABOUT
SOME GIANT FURRY CREATURE
THEY HAD.
I FIGURED IT MUST BE APPA.
Toph: HE WAS HERE!
WE MISSED HIM.
THEY TOOK
THAT BIG THING YESTERDAY.
SHIPPED HIM OUT TO SOME ISLAND.
ABOUT TIME.
I BEEN CLEANING UP FUR AND
VARIOUS, UH, LEAVINGS ALL DAY.
WHAT ISLAND?
WHERE'S APPA?
FOREMAN SAID SOME RICH ROYAL
TYPE ON WHALETAIL ISLAND
BOUGHT HIM UP,
GUESS FOR A ZOO OR SUCH, THOUGH
COULD BE THE MEAT'D BE GOOD.
WE'VE GOTTA GET TO
WHALETAIL ISLAND.
WHERE'S WHALETAIL ISLAND?
Sokka: FAR.
VERY FAR.
HERE IT IS.
IT'S NEAR THE SOUTH POLE,
ALMOST ALL THE WAY BACK HOME.
AANG, IT'LL TAKE US WEEKS
JUST TO GET TO THE TIP OF
THE EARTH KINGDOM.
AND THEN WE'LL NEED TO FIND
A BOAT TO GET TO THE ISLAND.
I DON'T CARE,
WE HAVE A CHANCE TO FIND APPA,
WE HAVE TO TRY.
Janitor: MUST BE NICE
TO VISIT AN ISLAND.
I HAVEN'T HAD
A VACATION FOR YEARS.
DON'T YOU HAVE SOME
MORE HAIR TO CLEAN UP?
SHUFFLE ON, I GET YA.
NO MORE NEED FOR OLD SWEEPY.
YOU'RE RIGHT, AANG.
RIGHT NOW, OUR FIRST CONCERN
HAS TO BE FINDING APPA.
WE CAN COME BACK
WHEN WE HAVE HIM.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET MOVING.
I'LL COME WITH YOU.
WE DON'T NEED YOUR HELP.
WHY WON'T YOU TRUST ME?
GEE, I WONDER.
WAS THIS GUY
YOUR BOYFRIEND OR SOMETHING?
WHAT, NO!
I CAN TELL YOU'RE LYING.
Sokka: WE CAN TAKE
THE TRAIN OUT TO THE WALL,
BUT THEN WE'LL HAVE TO WALK.
DON'T WORRY, ON THE WAY BACK,
WE'LL BE FLYING.
WE'RE FINALLY LEAVING
BA SING SE.
WORST CITY EVER!
JET!
I THOUGHT YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T
HAVE YOUR GANG ANYMORE.
I DON'T.
WE WERE SO WORRIED.
HOW DID YOU GET AWAY FROM
THE DAI LI?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT SHE'S TALKING ABOUT.
HE GOT ARRESTED BY THE DAI LI
A COUPLE WEEKS AGO.
WE SAW THEM DRAG HIM AWAY.
WHY WOULD I BE ARRESTED?
I'VE BEEN LIVING PEACEFULLY
IN THE CITY.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
THEY'RE BOTH TELLING THE TRUTH.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
TOPH CAN'T TELL WHO'S LYING
BECAUSE THEY BOTH THINK
THEY'RE TELLING THE TRUTH.
JET'S BEEN BRAINWASHED.
THAT'S CRAZY!
IT CAN'T BE.
STAY AWAY FROM ME!
[BELL RINGING]
Boy: OUT OF MY WAY, SKINNY.
UGH.
HUH?
[GASPING]
Boy: IF YOU DON'T WANT TO
END UP LIKE HIM,
YOU'LL DO WHAT I SAY.
[PURRING]
THE DAI LI MUST HAVE SENT JET TO
MISLEAD US, AND THAT JANITOR WAS
PART OF THEIR PLOT, TOO.
I BET THEY HAVE APPA
HERE IN THE CITY.
MAYBE HE'S IN THE SAME PLACE
THEY TOOK JET.
WHERE DID THEY TAKE YOU?
NOWHERE.
I, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
WE NEED TO FIND A WAY
TO JOG HIS REAL MEMORIES.
MAYBE KATARA COULD KISS HIM.
THAT SHOULD BRING
SOMETHING BACK.
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
KISS HIM, SOKKA.
HEY, JUST AN IDEA.
A BAD ONE.
OOH, WAIT, I GOT IT.
I DON'T THINK IT'S WORKING.
PUH!
Toph: TRY TO THINK OF SOMETHING
FROM YOUR PAST THAT TRIGGERS
YOUR EMOTIONS.
THE FIRE NATION, REMEMBER WHAT
THEY DID TO YOUR FAMILY?
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
PICTURE IT.
[SCREAMING]
NO!
IT'S TOO PAINFUL.
MAYBE THIS'LL HELP.
THEY TOOK ME TO A HEADQUARTERS
UNDER THE WATER, LIKE A LAKE.
WAIT, REMEMBER WHAT
JOO DEE SAID?
SHE SAID SHE WENT ON VACATION
TO LAKE LAOGAI.
THAT'S IT!
LAKE LAOGAI.
Sokka: SO WHERE'S THIS
SECRET HEADQUARTERS?
UNDER THE WATER, I THINK.
THERE'S A TUNNEL RIGHT THERE,
NEAR THE SHORE.
[WHISTLING]
[PURRING]
IT'S ALL STARTING TO
COME BACK TO ME.
Man: "I'M JOO DEE."
"WELCOME TO BA SING SE."
I'M JOO DEE.
WELCOME TO BA SING SE.
"WE'RE SO LUCKY TO HAVE
OUR WALLS TO CREATE ORDER."
WE'RE SO LUCKY TO HAVE
OUR WALLS TO CREATE ORDER.
I THINK THERE MIGHT BE
A CELL BIG ENOUGH TO HOLD APPA
UP AHEAD.
I THINK IT'S THROUGH HERE.
EXPECTING SOMEONE ELSE?
[GROWLING]
[GASPING]
NOW THAT'S SOMETHIN' DIFFERENT.
YOU HAVE MADE YOURSELVES
ENEMIES OF THE STATE.
TAKE THEM INTO CUSTODY.
[GROWLING]
[GRUNTING]
AH!
AUGH!
LONG FENG IS ESCAPING!
ALL RIGHT, AVATAR.
YOU'VE CAUSED ME
ENOUGH PROBLEMS.
THIS IS YOUR LAST CHANCE.
IF YOU WANT YOUR BISON BACK.
YOU DO HAVE APPA.
TELL ME WHERE HE IS!
AGREE TO EXIT THE CITY NOW,
AND I'LL WAIVE ALL CHARGES
AGAINST YOU AND ALLOW YOU
TO LEAVE WITH YOUR LOST PET.
YOU'RE IN NO POSITION
TO BARGAIN.
AM I NOT?
YOU'RE DEFINITELY NOT.
JET, THE EARTH KING HAS
INVITED YOU TO LAKE LAOGAI.
Jet: I AM HONORED TO ACCEPT
HIS INVITATION.
[SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
YOU'RE MINE, NOW.
UNCLE?
SO, THE BLUE SPIRIT.
I WONDER WHO COULD BE
BEHIND THAT MASK.
[SIGHING]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I WAS JUST ABOUT TO ASK YOU
THE SAME THING.
WHAT DO YOU PLAN TO DO NOW THAT
YOU'VE FOUND THE AVATAR'S BISON?
KEEP IT LOCKED
IN OUR NEW APARTMENT?
SHOULD I GO PUT ON
A POT OF TEA FOR HIM?
FIRST I HAVE TO
GET IT OUT OF HERE.
[SHOUTING]: AND THEN WHAT?
YOU NEVER THINK
THESE THINGS THROUGH.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN YOU CAPTURED THE AVATAR
AT THE NORTH POLE.
YOU HAD HIM,
AND THEN YOU HAD NOWHERE TO GO!
I WOULD'VE
FIGURED SOMETHING OUT.
NO!
IF HIS FRIENDS HADN'T
FOUND YOU, YOU WOULD HAVE
FROZEN TO DEATH!
[GROWLING]
I KNOW MY OWN DESTINY, UNCLE.
IS IT YOUR OWN DESTINY?
OR IS IT A DESTINY SOMEONE ELSE
HAS TRIED TO FORCE ON YOU?
STOP IT, UNCLE.
I HAVE TO DO THIS.
I'M BEGGING YOU, PRINCE ZUKO!
IT'S TIME FOR YOU TO
LOOK INWARD AND BEGIN ASKING
YOURSELF THE BIG QUESTIONS.
WHO ARE YOU,
AND WHAT DO YOU WANT?
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAM ECHOING]
JET, IT'S ME, AANG!
YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THIS.
I'M AFRAID HE NO LONGER
HAS A CHOICE.
Jet: [BREATHING HEAVILY]
AH, AH, AH!
[GROWLING]
JET, I'M YOUR FRIEND.
LOOK INSIDE YOUR HEART.
DO YOUR DUTY, JET.
HE CAN'T MAKE YOU DO THIS!
YOU'RE A FREEDOM FIGHTER.
[CHEERING]
DO IT, DO IT NOW!
[SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
FOOLISH BOY.
YOU'VE CHOSEN YOUR OWN DEMISE.
I'M SORRY, AANG.
DON'T BE.
THIS ISN'T GOOD.
YOU GUYS GO AND FIND APPA,
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF JET.
WE'RE NOT GONNA LEAVE YOU.
THERE'S NO TIME.
JUST GO.
WE'LL CARE OF HIM.
HE'S OUR LEADER.
DON'T WORRY, KATARA.
I'LL BE FINE.
HE'S LYING.
[CRYING]
Aang: APPA'S GONE!
LONG FENG BEAT US HERE.
IF WE KEEP MOVING, MAYBE WE CAN
CATCH UP WITH THEM.
YOU THINK WE COULD OUTRUN THEM?
I DON'T THINK IT'S GONNA MATTER.
[PURRING]
WHAT IS IT, MOMO?
Appa: [RUMBLING]
APPA!
[SCREAMING]
[RUMBLING]
[GROWLING]
I CAN HANDLE YOU BY MYSELF.
[CHEERING AND LAUGHTER]
Sokka: YEAH, APPA!
I MISSED YOU, BUDDY.
[RUMBLING]
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING, NEPHEW.
LEAVE IT BEHIND.
♪