Girl: WATER.
EARTH.
FIRE.
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
A HUNDRED YEARS PASSED,
AND MY BROTHER AND I
DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR,
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS
AIRBENDING SKILLS ARE GREAT,
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE
AANG CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
DON'T YOU KNOW FANS
JUST MAKE FLAME STRONGER?
I AM LONG FENG,
HEAD OF THE DAI LI.
WHY WON'T YOU LET US
TALK TO THE KING?
THE EARTH KING HAS NO TIME
TO GET INVOLVED WITH
POLITICAL SQUABBLES.
SO THE KING IS JUST
A FIGUREHEAD?
HE'S YOUR PUPPET!
IT'S TIME FOR YOU
TO LOOK INWARD,
AND BEGIN ASKING YOURSELF
THE BIG QUESTIONS.
WHO ARE YOU?
AND WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I CAN HANDLE YOU BY MYSELF.
[RUMBLING]
I MISSED YOU, BUDDY.
I MISSED YOU MORE THAN
YOU'LL EVER KNOW, BUDDY.
[LAUGHING]
LOOK, WE ESCAPED FROM
THE DAI LI, WE GOT APPA BACK,
I'M TELLING YOU, WE SHOULD GO TO
THE EARTH KING NOW AND TELL HIM
OUR PLAN.
WE'RE ON A ROLL.
ONE GOOD HOUR AFTER WEEKS OF
TROUBLE ISN'T MUCH OF A ROLL.
WE CAN BUILD ON IT.
IF WE WANT TO INVADE
THE FIRE NATION WHEN
THE ECLIPSE HAPPENS,
WE NEED
THE EARTH KING'S SUPPORT.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
WE'LL GET IT?
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE NOTICED,
BUT THINGS DON'T USUALLY GO THAT
SMOOTHLY FOR OUR LITTLE GANG.
I KNOW, BUT I'VE GOT
A GOOD FEELING ABOUT THIS.
THIS TIME'LL BE DIFFERENT.
SOKKA, LONG FENG IS IN CONTROL
OF THE CITY.
HIS CONSPIRACY WITH THE DAI LI
IS TOO POWERFUL.
I THINK WE SHOULD JUST
KEEP FLYING AND LEAVE THIS
HORRIBLE PLACE BEHIND US.
I'M WITH SWEETNESS.
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH OF BA SING SE.
AND I CAN'T EVEN SEE!
BUT NOW THAT WE HAVE APPA BACK,
THERE'S NOTHING STOPPING US
FROM TELLING THE EARTH KING
THE TRUTH.
ABOUT THE CONSPIRACY
AND THE WAR.
SEE, AANG'S WITH ME.
IT'S THE WHOLE REASON
WE CAME HERE IN THE FIRST PLACE,
WE HAVE TO TRY.
WELL, I GUESS IF THE EARTH KING
KNEW THE TRUTH,
THINGS COULD CHANGE.
I DON'T TRUST
THE NEW POSITIVE SOKKA.
[SHOUTING]: LONG FENG
BRAINWASHED YOU, DIDN'T HE?
THAT'S PROBABLY THE DAI LI
SEARCHING FOR US, SO?
LET'S FLY.
[ROARING]
CAN WE PLEASE BUY A NEW SADDLE?
RIDING BAREBACK IS TERRIFYING.
THERE IT IS.
THAT WHOLE THING IS THE PALACE.
THE EARTH KING'S CHAMBER
SHOULD BE IN THE CENTER.
WE HAVE TO BE CAREFUL.
LONG FENG'S PROBABLY WARNED
THE KING THAT WE'RE COMING.
Sokka: WHY WOULD YOU
ASSUME THAT?
IF YOU ASK ME, I THINK WE'RE
JUST GONNA SAIL RIGHT...
[SCREAMING]
Appa: [RUMBLING]
WHAT WAS THAT?
Sokka: SURFACE-TO-AIR ROCKS!
MORE INCOMING!
[SCREAMING]
Aang: [GRUNTING]
Soldiers: [GRUNTING
AND SCREAMING]
[GROWLING]
Soldiers: [SCREAMING]
Katara: SORRY!
[SCREAMING]
Katara: SORRY, WE JUST
NEED TO GET THROUGH
TO SEE THE EARTH KING.
Soldiers: [GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
Soldiers: [SCREAMING]
Sokka: SERIOUSLY, WE'RE ACTUALLY
ON YOUR GUYS' SIDE!
SORRY.
Sokka: IN THERE.
Appa: [RUMBLING]
[GRUNTING]
TOPH, WHICH WAY
TO THE EARTH KING?
HOW SHOULD I KNOW?
I'M STILL VOTING
WE LEAVE BA SING SE.
Soldiers: WHOA!
Soldier: [SCREAMING]
BURGLAR!
SORRY, WRONG DOOR.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
LETTING THE AVATAR'S BISON
GO FREE.
I DON'T FEEL RIGHT.
[GROANING]
ZUKO!
Sokka: NOW THAT'S
AN IMPRESSIVE DOOR.
IT'S GOTTA GO SOMEWHERE.
[SCREAMING] YAH!
[GRUNTING]
A LITTLE WARNING, NEXT TIME?
WE NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
THEY'RE HERE TO OVERTHROW YOU.
NO, WE'RE ON YOUR SIDE.
WE'RE HERE TO HELP.
YOU HAVE TO TRUST US.
YOU INVADE MY PALACE,
LAY WASTE TO ALL MY GUARDS,
BREAK DOWN MY FANCY DOOR,
AND YOU EXPECT ME TO TRUST YOU?
HE HAS A GOOD POINT.
King: IF YOU'RE ON MY SIDE,
THEN DROP YOUR WEAPONS
AND STAND DOWN.
SEE, WE'RE FRIENDS,
YOUR EARTHINESS.
[LAUGHING NERVOUSLY]
[GRUNTING]
Long Feng: DETAIN
THE ASSAILANTS.
BUT WE DROPPED OUR WEAPONS.
WE'RE YOUR ALLIES!
MAKE SURE THE AVATAR
AND HIS FRIENDS NEVER SEE
DAYLIGHT AGAIN.
THE AVATAR?
YOU'RE THE AVATAR?
UH, NO, HIM .
OVER HERE.
Long Feng: WHAT DOES IT MATTER,
YOUR HIGHNESS?
THEY'RE ENEMIES OF THE STATE.
PERHAPS YOU'RE RIGHT.
[RUMBLING]
[SNIFFING]
[LAUGHING]
THOUGH BOSCO SEEMS TO LIKE HIM.
I'LL HEAR WHAT HE HAS TO SAY.
Aang: WELL, SIR, THERE'S A WAR
GOING ON RIGHT NOW.
FOR THE PAST 100 YEARS, IN FACT.
THE DAI LI'S KEPT IT
SECRET FROM YOU.
IT'S A CONSPIRACY TO CONTROL
THE CITY AND TO CONTROL YOU.
A SECRET WAR?
THAT'S CRAZY!
COMPLETELY.
LONG FENG DIDN'T WANT US
TO TELL YOU,
SO HE STOLE OUR SKY BISON
TO BLACKMAIL US.
AND BLACKMAIL
IS THE LEAST OF HIS CRIMES.
HE BRAINWASHED OUR FRIEND!
ALL LIES.
I'VE NEVER EVEN SEEN
A SKY BISON, YOUR MAJESTY.
FRANKLY, I THOUGHT
THEY WERE EXTINCT.
YOUR CLAIM
IS DIFFICULT TO BELIEVE.
EVEN FROM AN AVATAR.
[WHISPERING]
THESE HOOLIGANS ARE PART OF
AN ANARCHIST CELL
THAT MY AGENTS HAVE BEEN
TRACKING FOR WEEKS.
IF YOU LISTEN TO THEM,
YOU'RE PLAYING RIGHT INTO
YOUR OWN DESTRUCTION.
I HAVE TO TRUST MY ADVISOR.
WAIT, I CAN PROVE HE'S LYING!
LONG FENG SAID HE'S NEVER SEEN
A SKY BISON.
ASK HIM TO LIFT HIS ROBE.
WHAT?
I AM NOT DISROBING.
Aang: RIGHT THERE, APPA BIT HIM!
NEVER MET A SKY BISON, HUH?
THAT HAPPENS TO BE
A LARGE BIRTHMARK.
THANKS FOR SHOWING EVERYONE.
WELL, I SUPPOSE THERE'S NO WAY
TO PROVE WHERE THOSE MARKS
CAME FROM.
OF COURSE THERE IS.
[RUMBLING]
YEP, THAT PRETTY MUCH PROVES IT.
[CHEERING]
BUT IT DOESN'T PROVE
THIS CRAZY CONSPIRACY THEORY.
[GROANING]
THOUGH, I SUPPOSE THIS MATTER
IS WORTH LOOKING INTO.
Kids: UH, O.K., WE'LL TAKE IT,
UH, YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
[MOANING]
YOU'RE BURNING UP.
YOU HAVE AN INTENSE FEVER.
THIS WILL HELP COOL YOU DOWN.
SO THIRSTY.
HERE'S SOME CLEAN WATER
TO DRINK.
STAY UNDER THE BLANKETS
AND SWEAT THIS OUT.
[COUGHING]
SO THIS IS WHAT A TRAIN IS LIKE.
I DIDN'T REALIZE IT WOULD BE
THIS... PUBLIC.
SO YOU'VE NEVER BEEN OUTSIDE
THE UPPER RING BEFORE?
I'VE NEVER BEEN OUTSIDE
THE PALACE.
NOW THAT'S THE WAY TO TRAVEL.
SO, MAY I ASK WHERE WE'RE GOING?
UNDERNEATH LAKE LAOGAI,
YOUR KINGLINESS.
TO THE DAI LI
SECRET HEADQUARTERS.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO SEE WHERE ALL
THE BRAINWASHING AND CONSPIRING
TOOK PLACE.
Toph: IT'S GONE!
OH, DON'T TELL ME...
THAT'S O.K., STILL GOT
MY POSITIVE ATTITUDE.
THE DAI LI MUST HAVE KNOWN
WE WERE COMING AND DESTROYED
THE EVIDENCE.
HMM, THAT SEEMS
AWFULLY CONVENIENT.
HEY, IF ANYTHING, THIS PROVES
THE CONSPIRACY EXISTS EVEN MORE.
LONG FENG WAS RIGHT,
THIS WAS A WASTE OF TIME.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
I'M GOING BACK TO THE PALACE.
THE WALL!
THEY'LL NEVER BE ABLE TO COVER
THAT UP IN TIME.
OH, YEAH.
IF YOU COME WITH US
TO THE OUTER WALL,
WE CAN PROVE TO YOU
THAT THE SECRET WAR IS REAL.
NO EARTH KING
HAS EVER BEEN TO THE OUTER WALL.
I DON'T HAVE ANY MORE TIME
FOR THIS NONSENSE.
IF YOU COME WITH US, THIS TIME
YOU CAN RIDE ON APPA.
[RUMBLING]
[SCREAMING]
FIRST TIME FLYING?
IT'S BOTH THRILLING
AND TERRIFYING.
YEAH, I HATE IT, TOO.
I HAVE TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
PART OF ME REALLY HOPES THAT
WHAT YOU'RE TELLING ME ABOUT THS
WAR...
ISN'T TRUE.
I WISH IT WASN'T.
[GROANING]
[FAINT CHANTING]
Girl: IT'S GETTING LATE.
ARE YOU PLANNING TO RETIRE SOON,
MY LORD?
I'M NOT TIRED.
Girl: RELAX, FIRE LORD ZUKO.
JUST LET GO.
GIVE IN TO IT.
SHUT YOUR EYES FOR A WHILE.
Uncle: NO, FIRE LORD ZUKO!
DO NOT LISTEN TO
THE BLUE DRAGON.
YOU SHOULD GET OUT OF HERE
RIGHT NOW.
GO!
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE!
Girl: SLEEP NOW, FIRE LORD ZUKO.
Girl: SLEEP.
JUST LIKE MOTHER!
ZUKO, HELP ME!
[SCREAMING]
IT'S STILL THERE!
WHAT IS THAT?
IT'S A DRILL.
A GIANT DRILL,
MADE BY THE FIRE NATION,
TO BREAK THROUGH YOUR WALLS.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I NEVER KNEW.
I CAN EXPLAIN THIS,
YOUR MAJESTY.
THIS IS NOTHING MORE THAN...
A CONSTRUCTION PROJECT.
REALLY?
THEN PERHAPS YOU COULD EXPLAIN
WHY THERE'S A FIRE NATION
INSIGNIA ON YOUR
CONSTRUCTION PROJECT.
WELL, IT'S IMPORTED, OF COURSE.
YOU KNOW YOU CAN'T TRUST
DOMESTIC MACHINERY.
SURELY YOU DON'T BELIEVE
THESE CHILDREN INSTEAD OF
YOUR MOST LOYAL ATTENDANT?
DAI LI, ARREST LONG FENG.
I WANT HIM TO STAND TRIAL
FOR CRIMES AGAINST
THE EARTH KINGDOM.
YOU CAN'T ARREST ME.
YOU ALL NEED ME
MORE THAN YOU KNOW!
LOOKS LIKE LONG FENG
IS LONG GONE!
HA...
OH, YEAH, I'VE BEEN WAITIN'
TO USE THAT ONE.
King: I WANT TO THANK YOU,
YOUNG HEROES,
FOR OPENING MY EYES.
ALL THIS TIME, WHAT I THOUGHT
WAS A GREAT METROPOLIS
WAS MERELY A CITY OF FOOLS.
AND THAT MAKES ME THE KING FOOL.
[RUMBLING]
WE'RE AT WAR
WITH THE FIRE NATION.
Sokka: THAT'S WHY WE CAME
TO BA SING SE, YOUR HIGHNESS.
BECAUSE WE THINK
YOU COULD HELP US END THE WAR.
Aang: WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
THERE'S A COMET COMING
THIS SUMMER.
ITS ENERGY
WILL GIVE THE FIREBENDERS
UNBELIEVABLE STRENGTH.
THEY'LL BE UNSTOPPABLE.
BUT THERE IS HOPE.
BEFORE THE COMET COMES,
WE HAVE A WINDOW OF OPPORTUNITY.
A SOLAR ECLIPSE IS COMING.
THE SUN WILL BE ENTIRELY
BLOCKED OUT BY THE MOON,
AND THE FIREBENDERS
WILL BE HELPLESS.
WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING, SOKKA?
THAT'S THE DAY WE NEED TO INVADE
THE FIRE NATION.
THE DAY OF BLACK SUN.
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT WOULD REQUIRE
MOVING TROOPS OUT OF BA SING SE.
WE'D BE COMPLETELY VULNERABLE.
YOU'RE ALREADY VULNERABLE.
THE FIRE NATION WON'T STOP
UNTIL BA SING SE FALLS.
YOU CAN EITHER SIT BACK
AND WAIT FOR THAT TO HAPPEN,
OR TAKE THE OFFENSIVE AND GIVE
YOURSELF A FIGHTING CHANCE.
VERY WELL.
YOU HAVE MY SUPPORT.
[CHEERING]
Man: YOUR MAJESTY.
I APOLOGIZE
FOR THE INTERRUPTION.
King: THIS IS GENERAL HOW.
HE'S THE LEADER OF
THE COUNCIL OF FIVE,
MY HIGHEST-RANKING GENERALS.
WE SEARCHED LONG FENG'S OFFICE.
I THINK WE FOUND SOMETHING
THAT WILL INTEREST EVERYBODY.
THERE ARE SECRET FILES
ON EVERYONE IN BA SING SE.
INCLUDING YOU KIDS.
SECRET FILES?
King: TOPH BEIFONG.
IT'S A LETTER FROM YOUR MOM.
YOUR MOM'S HERE IN THE CITY.
AND SHE WANTS TO SEE YOU.
LONG FENG INTERCEPTED
OUR LETTERS FROM HOME?
THAT'S JUST SAD.
King: AANG.
THIS SCROLL WAS ATTACHED TO
THE HORN OF YOUR BISON
WHEN THE DAI LI CAPTURED IT.
IT'S FROM
THE EASTERN AIR TEMPLE.
IS THERE A LETTER FOR ME
AND SOKKA, BY ANY CHANCE?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
OH.
BUT THERE IS AN INTELLIGENCE
REPORT THAT MIGHT INTEREST YOU.
A SMALL FLEET
OF WATER TRIBE SHIPS?
WHAT?
THAT COULD BE DAD!
PROTECTING THE MOUTH OF
CHAMELEON BAY?
LED BY HAKODA, IT IS DAD!
Uncle: YOU SHOULD KNOW
THIS IS NOT A NATURAL SICKNESS.
BUT THAT SHOULDN'T STOP YOU
FROM ENJOYING TEA.
WHAT, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
YOUR CRITICAL DECISION,
WHAT YOU DID BENEATH THAT LAKE,
IT WAS IN SUCH CONFLICT
WITH YOUR IMAGE OF YOURSELF
THAT YOU ARE NOW AT WAR
WITHIN YOUR OWN MIND AND BODY.
WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
[COUGHING]
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH
A METAMORPHOSIS, MY NEPHEW.
IT WILL NOT BE
A PLEASANT EXPERIENCE.
BUT WHEN YOU COME OUT OF IT,
YOU WILL BE
THE BEAUTIFUL PRINCE
YOU WERE ALWAYS MEANT TO BE.
Aang: I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE'S A MAN LIVING AT
THE EASTERN AIR TEMPLE.
HE SAYS HE'S A GURU.
WHAT'S A GURU?
SOME KIND OF POISONOUS BLOWFISH?
NO, A SPIRITUAL EXPERT.
HE WANTS TO HELP ME TAKE
THE NEXT STEP IN
THE AVATAR JOURNEY.
HE SAYS HE CAN TEACH ME
TO CONTROL THE AVATAR STATE.
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
WE KNOW WHERE OUR DAD IS NOW.
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
MY MOM'S IN THE CITY,
AND FROM HER LETTER,
IT SOUNDS LIKE SHE
FINALLY UNDERSTANDS ME.
THIS IS ALL SUCH BIG NEWS.
WHERE DO WE EVEN START?
I HATE TO SAY IT, BUT...
WE HAVE TO SPLIT UP.
SPLIT UP?
WE JUST FOUND APPA AND GOT
THE FAMILY BACK TOGETHER.
NOW YOU WANT US TO SEPARATE?
YOU HAVE TO
MEET THIS GURU, AANG.
IF WE'RE GONNA INVADE
THE FIRE NATION,
YOU NEED TO BE READY.
WELL, IF I'M GOING TO
THE EASTERN AIR TEMPLE,
APPA AND I CAN DROP YOU OFF
AT CHAMELEON BAY
TO SEE YOUR DAD.
SOMEONE HAS TO STAY HERE
WITH THE EARTH KING AND
HELP HIM PLAN FOR THE INVASION.
I GUESS THAT'S ME.
NO, SOKKA, I KNOW HOW BADLY
YOU WANT TO HELP DAD.
YOU GO TO CHAMELEON BAY,
I'LL STAY HERE WITH THE KING.
YOU ARE THE...
NICEST... SISTER...EVER!
[KISSING]
EASY THERE, BIG BROTHER.
THOUGH YOU'RE RIGHT, I AM.
Aang: KATARA, I NEED TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
I'VE BEEN WANTING TO SAY IT
FOR A LONG TIME.
WHAT IS IT, AANG?
KATARA, I...
ALL RIGHT!
WHO'S READY TO GET GOING ON
A LITTLE MEN-ONLY, MAN TRIP?
AANG AND SOKKA,
I WISH YOU A GOOD JOURNEY.
BA SING SE OWES YOU ITS THANKS.
AND WE LOOK FORWARD TO
YOUR SAFE RETURN.
Guard: YOUR MAJESTY,
THERE ARE THREE FEMALE WARRIORS
HERE TO SEE YOU.
THEY'RE FROM
THE ISLAND OF KYOSHI.
THAT'S SUKI!
[SCREAMING]
YOU KNOW THESE WARRIORS?
OH, YEAH.
THE KYOSHI WARRIORS
ARE A SKILLED GROUP OF FIGHTERS.
TRUSTWORTHY, TOO.
THEY'RE GOOD FRIENDS OF OURS.
THEN WE SHALL WELCOME THEM
AS HONORED GUESTS.
Katara: WAIT, AANG.
[KISSING]
Toph: I'M REALLY GONNA
MISS YOU GUYS.
Katara: ME, TOO.
Aang: YEAH.
[SCREAMING]
GREAT, THAT'S ENOUGH.
O.K., WE LOVE EACH OTHER.
SERIOUSLY.
[RUMBLING]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
Sokka: YOU SEE, AANG?
A LITTLE POSITIVE THINKING
WORKS WONDERS.
WE GOT THE KING ON OUR SIDE,
WE GOT LONG FENG ARRESTED,
AND WHEN WE GET BACK,
SUKI'S WAITING FOR ME.
YEAH.
GIRLS ARE WAITING FOR US.
THANKS, POSITIVE ATTITUDE.
EVERYTHING IS GONNA
WORK OUT PERFECTLY.
FROM NOW ON AND FOREVER.
Man: DINNER.
THE COUNCIL OF FIVE
AND THE MILITARY ARE LOYAL
TO THE EARTH KING.
BUT THE DAI LI REMAINS LOYAL
TO YOU, LONG FENG, SIR.
[SIGHING]
HELLO, MOM?
ANYONE HOME?
[SCREAMING]
HEY!
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DEALING WITH?
ONE LOUDMOUTHED LITTLE BRAT
WHO STRAYED TOO FAR FROM HOME.
King: IN OUR HOUR OF NEED,
IT IS WITH THE HIGHEST HONOR
THAT I WELCOME
OUR ESTEEMED ALLIES,
THE KYOSHI WARRIORS.
WE ARE THE EARTH KING'S
HUMBLE SERVANTS.
♪