- KATARA: Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I discovered
the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
- Ugh!
- KATARA: But I believe
Aang can save the world.
♪
- AANG: There's a man living
at the Eastern Air Temple.
He says he can teach me
to control the Avatar State.
- In the Avatar State,
you are at your most powerful.
But you are also
at your most vulnerable.
- What do you mean?
- If you are killed
in the Avatar State,
the reincarnation
cycle will be broken,
and the Avatar
will cease to exist.
- What's happening?
- You are going through
a metamorphosis, my nephew.
- The Dai Li remains loyal
to you, Long Feng, sir.
- Hello?
[screams]
- It is with
the highest honor
that I welcome
the Kyoshi Warriors.
- We are the Earth King's
humble servants.
♪
- ZUKO:
[yawning]
What's that smell?
- It's jook. I'm sure
you wouldn't like it.
- [inhaling]
Actually, it smells delicious.
I'd love a bowl, Uncle.
- Now that your fever is gone,
you seem different somehow.
- It's a new day.
We've got a new apartment,
new furniture,
and today's the grand opening
of your new tea shop.
Things are looking
up, Uncle.
[sipping liquid]
- You haven't seen your
Dad in over two years.
You must be so excited.
- [retches]
I know I should be, but I just
feel sick to my stomach.
- Don't be nervous, he's gonna
be so happy to see you.
- So what about you?
Are you nervous
to meet this Guru?
- Not at all.
I'm ready to master
the Avatar State.
I'll do whatever
it takes.
See you in a week.
Yip! Yip!
- [heavy sigh]
♪
- Sokka, good to see you.
- WARRIORS: [laughing]
♪
- Sokka.
- Hi, Dad.
♪
- Look, Bosco,
the Kyoshi Warriors
are here to protect us.
Aren't you excited?
- [yawning]
- It's been a difficult
week for me.
My most trusted advisor,
Long Feng, and his Dai Li agents
tried to take control
of Ba Sing Se from me.
- It's terrible
when you can't trust
the people who are
closest to you.
- But there is good news.
As we speak, the Council of Five
is meeting to plan an invasion
of The Fire Nation this summer--
on the day of a solar eclipse.
- Really?
Now that sounds like a
fascinating and brilliant plan.
- General Fong's base
will serve as the launching
point for the attack.
In exactly two months,
the Army and Navy will invade
the Fire Nation
on The Day of Black Sun.
- Or we could send in
Momo to do some damage.
[laughing]
'cause the...
Sorry.
- [screeching]
- All we need is
the Earth King's seal
in order to execute
the plan.
- I'll get these scrolls
to him right away.
Thank you, General How.
- APPA:
[grunting]
♪
- Um, Hello?
You're Guru Pathik, right?
The person who attached
the note to Appa's horn?
- Indeed.
I was a spiritual brother
of your people,
and a personal friend
of Monk Gyatso.
- In your note, you said
you could teach me
to gain control
of the Avatar State.
How?
- You must gain balance
within yourself
before you can bring
balance to the world.
And the first step to gaining
balance begins with this.
Drink up.
- [sipping, spitting]
Ugh!
It tastes like onion
and banana juice!
- That's because it is.
[slurping]
Yum! Yum!
- I believe we need
to go right!
- What are you
talking about?
The Bei Fong Estate's
this way.
- I'm quite certain
you're mistaken.
- [loud banging]
Hey, can you two old ladies quit
your bickering for a second?
I gotta go to the bathroom!
- Oh...uh...
Okay, but make it quick.
- What's wrong with you?!
- Oh, very sneaky, Toph!
Nice try,
but you can't trick me.
- Let me outta here,
so I can kick both your butts!
- Quit your banging!
You might think you're
the greatest Earthbender
in the world, but even
you can't bend metal.
- ♪
- We have been
presented with
an extraordinary
opportunity, girls.
- Mai finally gets
to wear makeup
that's not totally
depressing?
- Ha. Ha.
- I'm talking about conquering
the whole Earth Kingdom.
For a hundred years the Fire
Nation has hammered away
at Ba Sing Se
from the outside.
But now we are on the inside,
and we can take it by ourselves.
- Gosh, you're so confident.
I really admire that about you.
- From the inside, we're
in perfect position
to organize a coup
and overthrow the Earth King.
The key is the Dai Li.
Whoever controls the Dai Li,
controls Ba Sing Se.
- In order to master
the Avatar State,
you must open
all the chakras.
Aang, tell me everything
you know about chakras.
- What are chakras?
- Oh, I see.
I guess we'll start
with the basics.
The water flows
through this creek
much like the energy flows
through your body.
As you see there
are several pools
where the water swirls
around before flowing on.
These pools are
like our chakras.
- So, chakras are pools of
spiraling energy in our bodies?
- Exactly. If nothing
else were around,
this creek would
flow pure and clear.
However, life is messy,
and things tend
to fall in the creek,
and then what happens?
- The creek can't flow?
- Yes.
But if we open the paths
between the pools...
- The energy flows!
- [water gurgling]
- There are seven chakras
that go up the body.
Each pool of energy
has a purpose,
and can be blocked by a
specific kind of emotional muck.
Be warned--opening the chakras
is an intense experience,
and once you begin
this process,
you cannot stop until
all seven are open.
Are you ready?
- I'll do whatever it takes.
- First we will open
the Earth chakra,
located at the base
of the spine.
It deals with survival
and is blocked by fear.
What are you
most afraid of?
- [dramatic music]
- Let your fears
become clear to you.
- [dramatic music]
- [screaming]
- GURU: Aang, your vision
is not real.
You are concerned
for your survival,
but you must surrender
those fears.
Let your fears
flow down the creek.
- ♪
- You have opened
your Earth chakra.
- Whew.
- [water cascading]
- ♪
- Next is the...
- Water chakra?
- Brilliant!
Maybe one day you
will be a Guru, too.
This chakra deals with pleasure,
and is blocked by guilt.
Now, look at all the guilt
which burdens you so.
What do you blame
yourself for?
- ♪
- AANG:
I ran away.
♪
- I hurt all
of those people.
- Accept the reality that
these things happened,
but do not let them cloud
and poison your energy.
If you are to be a positive
influence on the world,
you need to
forgive yourself.
- ♪
- This bay leads directly to
the outskirts of Ba Sing Se.
We've been using
these tangle mines
to stop the Fire Nation
ships from getting through.
- Your father invented
tangle mines, himself.
- Destructive,
buoyant, and...
[sniffing]
[gasps]
...terrible smelling!
- Very perceptive.
The mines are filled with
skunk-fish and seaweed.
When a ship
detonates the mine,
the seaweed tangles
up the propeller,
and the foul smell forces
people to abandon the ship.
I call it
the stink n' sink.
- [laughing]
Good one, Dad!
- You are definitely
your father's son.
- Hakoda, our scouts have
spotted four Fire Nation ships.
- Bato, get these
mines loaded up.
The rest of you men,
prepare for battle.
- Um, what should
I do, Dad?
- Aren't you listening?
I said the rest of you men
get ready for battle.
♪
- Who thought when we came
to this city as refugees,
that I'd end up
owning my own tea shop.
Follow your passion, Zuko,
and life will reward you.
- Congratulations, Uncle.
- I'm very thankful.
- You deserve it.
The Jasmine Dragon will be
the best tea shop in the city.
- No, I'm thankful
because you decided
to share this special
day with me.
It means more
than you know.
- Now let's make these
people some tea.
- Yes, let's make
some tea!
♪
- Third is the Fire chakra,
located in the stomach.
- My Fire chakra would
like to eat something
other than onion-
banana juice.
- [chuckling]
Good one. Moving on.
This chakra deals with will
power and is blocked by shame.
What are you ashamed of?
What are your biggest
disappointments in yourself?
♪
- I'm never gonna
fire bend again.
I can't.
- You will never
find balance,
if you deny this
part of your life.
You are the Avatar,
and therefore,
you are a Firebender.
- [inhales, exhales]
- Hmmm, that chakra opened
less like a flowing creek,
and more like a...
burping bison.
- [huge belch]
Tastes like onion and bananas,
but, strangely, something else.
Pickles?
- [shrugs "I don't know"]
- ♪
- I'm tired of wearing
this girly disguise.
I don't know how anyone
can fight in this.
- Maybe that's why
it was so easy
to beat the Kyoshi Warriors
and take their clothes.
- How much longer do we have
to serve the Earth King?
If I have to clean up one
more pile of bear poop,
I'm gonna throw up.
- Princess Azula promised we
would go back to the Fire Nation
as soon as we captured
the Avatar.
We just have to be patient.
- Shush up!
Do you want the whole palace
to know we're Fire Nation?
- Sorry.
- ♪
- Good work, girls.
I am sure the Dai Li
will deliver the message.
- The fourth chakra
is located in the heart.
It deals with love,
and is blocked by grief.
Lay all your grief
out in front of you.
♪
- ♪
- You have, indeed,
felt a great loss.
But love is a form of energy,
and it swirls all around us.
The Air Nomads' love for you
has not left this world.
It is still inside
of your heart,
and is reborn in
the form of new love.
Let the pain flow away.
Very good.
- Can I have some onion-
banana juice, please?
- ♪
- The fifth in the chain
is the Sound chakra,
located in the throat.
It deals with truth,
and is blocked by lies--
the ones we tell ourselves.
- Why didn't you tell
us you were the Avatar?
- Because I never
wanted to be.
- You cannot lie
about your own nature.
You must accept that
you are the Avatar.
- [inhaling, exhaling]
- ♪
- Very good, Aang.
You have opened
the chakra of Truth.
The sixth pool of energy
is the Light chakra,
located in the center
of the forehead.
It deals with insight
and is blocked by illusion.
The greatest illusion
of this world
is the illusion
of separation.
Things you think are
separate and different
are actually one
and the same.
- Like the four nations.
- Yes, we are all one people,
but we live as if divided.
- We're all connected.
Everything is connected.
- That's right.
Even the separation of the four
elements is an illusion.
If you open your mind,
you will see that all
the elements are one--
four parts of
the same whole.
Even metal is just
a part of Earth
that has been purified
and refined.
- ♪
- [inhales, exhales]
- [straining]
Come on metal...budge.
- [metal thuds]
- Woo! Toph, you rule!
- What do you say, Momo?
A cup of tea before
we get back to the king?
- [chattering]
- Table for two, please.
- Uncle, I need two jasmine,
one green and one lychee.
- I'm brewing
as fast as I can.
- [dramatic music]
- ♪
- AANG: This is the last
chakra, isn't it?
- GURU:
Yes.
Once you open this chakra,
you will be able go in and out
of the Avatar State at will.
And when you are in
the Avatar State,
you will have
complete control
and awareness
of all your actions.
- Let's do this.
- The Thought chakra is located
at the crown of the head.
It deals with pure
cosmic energy
and is blocked
by earthly attachment.
Meditate on what attaches
you to this world.
- ♪
- Now, let all of
those attachments go.
Let them flow
down the river...
forgotten.
- What? Why would
I let go of Katara?
I...I love her.
- Learn to let her go,
or you cannot let
the pure cosmic energy
flow in from the universe.
- Why would I choose
cosmic energy over Katara?
How could it be a bad thing that
I feel an attachment to her?
Three chakras ago,
that was a good thing.
- You must learn
to let go.
- [panting]
Thank goodness
you're here, Suki.
Something terrible
is going on.
The Fire Nation has
infiltrated the city.
I just saw Prince Zuko
and his uncle!
We have to tell
the Earth King right away!
- Oh, don't worry.
I'll be sure to let him know.
- [screeches]
- ♪
- [gasps]
[grunts]
- AZULA: So, Zu Zu's
in the city, too.
I think it's time
for a family reunion.
- [chattering]
- I'm sorry, but I can't
let go of Katara.
- Aang, to master
the Avatar State,
you must open
all the chakras.
Surrender yourself.
- Okay, I'll try.
- ♪
- Now, think of your
attachments and let them go.
Let the pure cosmic
energy flow.
♪
- ♪
- KATARA:
[screams]
Let me go!
[straining]
- ♪
- [panting]
- [screaming]
Katara is in danger!
I have to go!
- No, Aang!
By choosing attachment,
you have locked the chakra!
If you leave now,
you won't be able to
go into the Avatar
State at all!
- ♪
- [metal clangs]
- It's another
one of her tricks.
- There's a giant
hole in the box.
How is that a trick?
- It's not!
It's the real deal!
- ♪
- I am the greatest
Earthbender in the world!
Don't you two dunderheads
ever forget!
- ♪
- I'm going to be stuck in here
forever with you, aren't I?
- I have to go
to the bathroom.
- [metal clangs]
- Ready to go knock
some Fire Nation heads?
- You don't know how much
this means to me, Dad.
I'll make you proud,
and I'll finally prove to you
what a great warrior I am.
- Sokka, you don't have
to prove anything to me.
I'm already proud of you,
and I've always known
you were a great warrior.
- Really?
- Why do you think
I trusted you
to look after
our tribe when I left?
♪
- This can't be good news.
- What is this about?
Your agents show up in
the middle of the night
and drag me down here?
You will not treat
a Kyoshi Warrior this way!
- But you are not
a Kyoshi Warrior, are you,
Princess Azula
of the Fire Nation?
- What do you want?
- I want to make a deal.
It's time that I regain
control of Ba Sing Se,
and you have
something I need.
- Oh?
- The Earth King's trust.
- Why should I help you?
- Because I can get
you the Avatar.
- I'm listening.
- A message from
the royal palace.
- I...I can't
believe it.
- What is it, Uncle?
- Great news!
We've been invited to serve
tea to the Earth King!
♪
- [metal door slams]
- [dramatic music]
- [lapping water]
- APPA: [grunting]
- [squawking]
- So, what kind of
trouble is Katara in?
- I don't know.
In my vision, I just
knew she needed help.
- It would be nice
if your Avatar powers
could be just a little more
specific from time to time.
- [loud rumbling]
- What is that?
♪
- Need a ride?
- [gasping]
- BOTH:
Ohhhh...
- The Earth King
and The Council of Five
do not trust the Dai Li.
They imprisoned
your leader, Long Feng.
Soon they will turn on all
of you and eliminate you.
Seizing power today
is a matter of life and death.
This coup must be
swift and decisive.
The Earth King, and each
of the five generals,
must be taken out,
simultaneously.
Long Feng has placed
you in my command
while we overthrow
the government.
If I sense any disloyalty,
any hesitation,
any weakness at all,
I will snuff it out.
- [dramatic music]
- That is all.
- Nice speech, Azula.
It was pretty and poetic,
but also scary in a good way.
- Yeah, I thought you were gonna
make that one guy pee his pants.
- There are still
a few loose ends--
the Avatar, and my brother
and uncle.
- Many times,
I imagined myself here--
at the threshold
of the palace.
But I always thought I would
be here as a conqueror.
Instead, we are the Earth King's
personal guests,
here to serve him tea.
Destiny is a funny thing.
- It sure is, Uncle.
- TOPH: So, how did it
go with the Guru?
Did you master
the Avatar State?
- Uh...
- If you leave now,
you won't be able to go into
the Avatar State at all!
- SOKKA:
Aang, are you okay?
- I'm great.
It went great
with the Guru.
I completely mastered
the Avatar State.
[self-conscious
laughter]
Yeah.
- What's taking so long?
- Maybe the Earth King
overslept.
- Something's not right.
- ♪
- AZULA:
It's tea time.
- Azula!
- Have you met
the Dai Li?
They're Earthbenders,
but they have a killer instinct
that's so Firebender.
I just love it.
- Did I ever tell you
how I got the nickname
the "Dragon of the West"?
- I'm not interested in
a lengthy anecdote, Uncle.
- It's more of
a demonstration, really.
[sipping tea]
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [explosion]
- [screaming]
[grunts]
Come on!
You'll be fine!
- No. I'm tired
of running.
It's time I faced Azula.
- ♪
- AZULA:
You're so dramatic.
What? Are you going to
challenge me to an Agni Kai?
- Yes! I challenge you!
- No, thanks.
- [roar of effort]
- ♪
- Oh!
[straining]
- APPA:
[growling]
- Katara's fine.
You have nothing
to worry about.
- But, in my vision...
I felt so sure that
she was in trouble.
- Well, she met with
the Council of Generals
to plan the invasion.
And since then she's been
off with your friends,
the Kyoshi Warriors.
- See Aang?
She's with Suki.
They're probably back at
our apartment right now,
talking about
makeup or something.
- Okay, maybe
you're right.
- Believe me, if there
was any danger at all,
Bosco's animal
instincts would sense it.
- [sleepy growling]
- ♪
- [loud rumbling]
- You've got company.
- [gasping, grunting]
- Zuko!
- [dramatic music]
- [loud rumbling]
- Momo!
- [chattering]
- There's no one
else here.
- Katara is in trouble.
I knew it.
- Oh, no.
- Wait, someone's
at the door.
- [knocking on door]
- Actually,
I know who it is.
It's an old friend
of mine.
Glad to see you're okay.
- I need your help.
- AANG &amp; SOKKA:
[gasp]
- [chattering]
- You guys know
each other?
- I met him in the woods
once and knocked him down.
Then he gave me tea
and some very good advice.
- May I come in?
Princess Azula
is here in Ba Sing Se.
- She must have Katara.
- She has captured
my nephew, as well.
- Then we'll work together
to fight Azula,
and save Katara and Zuko.
- Whoa, there.
You lost me at, "Zuko".
- I know how you must
feel about my nephew.
But believe me when I tell
you there is good inside him.
- Good inside him
isn't enough.
Why don't you come back when
it's outside him, too, okay?
- Katara's in trouble.
All of Ba Sing Se
is in trouble.
Working together
is our best chance.
- Mmm...
- I brought someone along
who might be able to help us.
- [muffled gasping]
Azula and Long Feng
are plotting a coup.
They're going to over-
throw the Earth King.
- My sister!
Where are they
keeping Katara?
- In the crystal catacombs
of old Ba Sing Se,
deep beneath the palace.
- [dramatic music]
- The movements of all
the generals and the Earth King
have been plotted
out step-by-step.
- Good.
And the Fire Nation Princess
is cooperating?
- Oh, yes, more
than cooperating--
she's really taken charge.
She's terrifying
and inspirational
at the same time.
It's hard to explain.
- ♪
- Why did they throw
you in here?
Oh, wait. Let me guess--
it's a trap,
so that when Aang
shows up to help me,
you can finally have him
in your little
Fire Nation clutches.
You're a terrible
person, you know that?
Always following us,
hunting the Avatar,
trying to capture the world's
last hope for peace!
But what do you care?
You're the Fire Lord's son.
Spreading war and violence
and hatred is in your blood.
- You don't know what
you're talking about.
- I don't? How dare you!
You have no idea what this
war has put me through.
Me, personally.
The Fire Nation took
my mother away from me.
- I'm sorry.
- [sobbing]
- That's something
we have in common.
- Well, what do ya know?
There is an ancient city
down there, but it's deep.
- [loud rumbling]
- We should split up.
Aang, you go with Iroh
to look for Katara
and the angry jerk,
no offense.
- None taken.
- And I'll go with Toph
to warn the Earth King
about Azula's coup.
- ♪
- So, Toph thinks you
give pretty good advice--
and great tea.
- The key to both
is proper aging.
What's on your mind?
- Well, I met with this
Guru who was supposed to
help me master the Avatar State,
and control this great power.
But to do it, I had to
let go of someone I love,
and I just couldn't.
- Perfection and power
are overrated.
I think you were very wise
to choose happiness and love.
- What happens if we can't
save everyone and beat Azula?
Without the Avatar State,
what if I'm not powerful enough?
- I don't know the answer.
Sometimes life is like
this dark tunnel.
You can't always see the light
at the end of the tunnel,
but if you just
keep moving...
...you will come
to a better place.
- There's General How.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [straining]
What's going on here?
- You're under
house arrest.
- The coup is
happening right now.
We've gotta warn
the Earth King.
♪
- [screaming]
- ♪
- BOTH:
[screaming]
- Thank goodness
we're in time!
- In time for what?
- Yeah, what are
you in time for...
...cutie?
- Uh, I'm kinda
involved with Suki.
- Who?
[gasps]
- They're not the real
Kyoshi Warriors!
- [gasps]
- Sorry to disappoint you.
- ♪
- [laughing]
- [gasps]
[gasping]
- Oooh, it's like
we're dancing together.
- This fight is over.
- ♪
- Get them all
out of my sight.
♪
- Now comes the part
where I double-cross you.
Dai Li, arrest the Fire
Nation Princess.
I said, arrest her.
What is wrong with you?
- It's because they
haven't made up their minds.
They're waiting to see
how this is going to end.
- What are you
talking about?
- I can see your whole
history in your eyes.
You were born with nothing,
so, you've had to struggle
and connive and claw
your way to power.
But true power,
the divine right to rule,
is something
you're born with.
The fact is, they don't
know which one of us
is going to be sitting
on that throne
and which one is going
to be bowing down.
But I know and you know.
Well?
- [dramatic music]
- You've beaten
me at my own game.
- Don't flatter yourself.
You were never
even a player.
- I'm sorry I yelled
at you before.
- It doesn't matter.
- It's just that
for so long now,
whenever I would imagine
the face of the enemy,
it was your face.
- My face.
I see.
- No, no, that's not
what I meant.
- It's okay.
I used to think this
scar marked me.
The mark of
the banished prince,
cursed to chase
the Avatar forever.
But lately, I've realized
I'm free to determine
my own destiny, even if
I'll never be free of my mark.
- Maybe you could
be free of it.
- What?
- I have healing abilities.
- It's a scar.
It can't be healed.
- This is water from the Spirit
Oasis at the North Pole.
It has special properties,
so I've been saving it
for something important.
I don't know if
it would work, but...
♪
- [rocks shattering]
- Aang!
- [dramatic music]
- Aang, I knew you
would come.
- Uncle,
I don't understand.
What are you doing
with the Avatar?
- Saving you.
That's what.
- [groans]
- Zuko, it's time we talked.
Go help your other friends.
We'll catch up with you.
- ♪
- Why, Uncle?
- You are not the man
you used to be, Zuko.
You are stronger and wiser
and freer than
you have ever been.
And now you have come to
the crossroads of your destiny.
It's time for
you to choose.
It's time for you
to choose good.
- [loud rumbling]
- [gasps]
- I expected this kind
of treachery from Uncle,
but Zuko, Prince Zuko,
you're a lot of things,
but you're not
a traitor, are you?
- Release him,
immediately!
- It's not too
late for you, Zuko.
You can still
redeem yourself.
- The kind of redemption
she offers is not for you.
Why don't you let
him decide, Uncle?
I need you, Zuko.
I've plotted every
move of this day,
this glorious day in
Fire Nation history,
and the only way
we win is together.
At the end of this day,
you will have your honor back.
You will have
Father's love.
everything you want.
- Zuko, I am begging you,
look into your heart and see
what it is that you truly want.
- You are free to choose.
♪
- We've gotta find
Sokka and Toph.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [gasps]
- [grunt of effort]
- ♪
- [grunts of effort]
- See any Dai Li
agents nearby?
- Nope. All clear.
- [metal thudding]
- Let's go!
- I'm not leaving
without Bosco!
- [grunts of effort]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[groans]
- ♪
- [grunt of effort]
- [grunting]
- [gasps]
♪
- ♪
- [grunt of effort]
- [grunting]
♪
- ♪
- [groaning]
- I thought you
had changed!
[grunt of effort]
- I have changed.
♪
- ♪
- Come on, it's easy.
You just walk on your front paws
instead of your rear ones,
like this...
[gasping]
- [happy growling,
applauding]
- That is a nice trick.
- Just take the bear.
- Bosco!
- [growling]
- ♪
- [gasps]
[groans]
- [loud rumbling]
- [roar of effort]
♪
- [screaming]
[grunts]
♪
- [groans]
- AANG: [thinking]
There's too many.
- GURU's VOICE: The only way
is to let her go.
- I'm sorry, Katara.
♪
- ♪
- [thunder crashing]
- [electrical zapping]
♪
- ♪
- ALL:
[screaming]
♪
- You've got to get
out of here!
I'll hold them off
as long as I can!
[grunts of effort]
♪
- ♪
- APPA:
[quiet growling]
♪
- Oh...
- [sighs]
- [gasps]
♪
- [dramatic music]
- AZULA:
We've done it, Zuko.
It's taken a hundred years,
but the Fire Nation
has conquered Ba Sing Se.
- I betrayed Uncle.
- No, he betrayed you.
Zuko, when you
return home,
Father will welcome
you as a war hero.
- But I don't have
the Avatar.
What if Father doesn't
restore my honor?
- He doesn't
need to, Zuko.
Today, you restored
your own honor.
♪
- The Earth Kingdom...
has fallen.
♪