Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO...
THE FOUR NATIONS LIVED
TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED AND MY BROTHER
AND I DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS WERE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Ozai: I AM PROUD OF YOU,
PRINCE ZUKO.
I AM PROUD BECAUSE WHEN YOUR
LOYALTY WAS TESTED
BY YOUR TREACHEROUS UNCLE
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING
AND CAPTURED THE TRAITOR.
Zuko: WHY DID YOU TELL FATHER
THAT I WAS THE ONE
WHO KILLED THE AVATAR?
PLEASE, ZUKO...
WHAT ULTERIOR MOTIVE
COULD I HAVE
UNLESS SOMEHOW THE AVATAR
WAS ACTUALLY ALIVE?
ALL THAT GLORY WOULD
SUDDENLY TURN TO SHAME.
♪
WHO'S THERE?
[WIND HOWLING]
Aang: I THINK I SEE
A CAVE BELOW.
Sokka: SHH... KEEP QUIET.
[BIRD SQUAWKS]
[APPA GRUNTS]
GREAT JOB WITH THE CLOUD CAMO,
BUT NEXT TIME...
LET'S DISGUISE OURSELVES
AS THE KIND OF CLOUD WHO KNOWS
HOW TO KEEP ITS MOUTH SHUT.
Toph: YEAH, WE WOULDN'T WANT
A BIRD TO HEAR US CHATTING UP
THERE AND TURN US IN.
HEY, WE'RE IN ENEMY TERRITORY.
THOSE ARE ENEMY BIRDS.
[SQUAWK]
[CHUCKLING]
[CRASHES]
Sokka: WELL, THIS IS IT.
THIS IS HOW WE'LL BE LIVING
UNTIL THE INVASION BEGINS.
HIDING IN CAVE AFTER CAVE...
AFTER CAVE AFTER CAVE...
SOKKA, WE DON'T NEED
TO BECOME CAVE PEOPLE.
WHAT WE NEED
IS SOME NEW CLOTHES.
YEAH, BLENDING IN
IS BETTER THAN HIDING OUT.
IF WE GET FIRE NATION DISGUISES
WE'LL BE JUST AS SAFE AS WE
WOULD BE HIDING IN A CAVE.
PLUS, THEY HAVE
REAL FOOD OUT THERE.
DOES ANYONE WANNA SIT IN THE
DIRT AND EAT CAVE-HOPPERS?
[CRUNCHING]
LOOKS LIKE WE
GOT OUTVOTED, SPORT.
LET'S GET SOME NEW CLOTHES.
Aang: I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS.
THESE CLOTHES
BELONG TO SOMEBODY.
I CALL THE SILK ROBE.
BUT IF IT'S ESSENTIAL
TO OUR SURVIVAL
THEN I CALL THE SUIT.
TA-DAH... NORMAL KID.
HMM... I SHOULD
PROBABLY WEAR SHOES
BUT THEN I WON'T
BE ABLE TO SEE AS WELL.
SORRY SHOES...
FINALLY, A STYLISH SHOE
FOR THE BLIND EARTHBENDER.
HOW DO I LOOK?
UH, YOUR MOM'S NECKLACE.
OH... OH, YEAH.
I GUESS IT'S PRETTY OBVIOUSLY
WATER TRIBE, ISN'T IT?
[MOMO PURRS]
I USED TO VISIT MY FRIEND
KUZON HERE 100 YEARS AGO.
SO EVERYONE JUST FOLLOW
MY LEAD AND STAY COOL.
OR AS THEY SAY
IN THE FIRE NATION
"STAY FLAMIN'".
GREETINGS, MY GOOD HOTMAN.
OH, HI...
I GUESS?
Aang: OH, WE'RE GOING
TO A MEAT PLACE?
Sokka: COME ON, AANG,
EVERYONE HERE EATS MEAT...
EVEN THE MEAT.
[GROWLS]
YOU GUYS GO AHEAD.
I'LL JUST GET SOME LETTUCE
OUT OF THE GARBAGE.
Aang: HOTMAN, HOTMAN.
HOTMAN.
HOTMAN, HOTMAN.
IT'S OVER,
WE CAUGHT YOU.
WHO ME?
IT COULDN'T BE MORE OBVIOUS
THAT YOU DON'T BELONG HERE.
NEXT TIME YOU PLAY HOOKY
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE OFF
YOUR SCHOOL UNIFORM.
[NERVOUS CHUCKLE]... AH!
OH...
Teacher: IS THIS A NEW MIND
READY FOR MOLDING?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LET THE MOLDING BEGIN.
Teacher: WAIT A MINUTE.
[GASPS]: YOU'RE NOT
FROM THE FIRE NATION.
CLEARLY YOU'RE
FROM THE COLONIES.
YEAH, THE COLONIES,
OF COURSE.
THE FIRE NATION COLONIES
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM.
YOUR ETIQUETTE
IS TERRIBLE.
IN THE HOMELAND,
WE BOW TO OUR ELDERS...
LIKE SO.
SORRY MA'AM.
AND WE DON'T WEAR
HEAD COVERINGS INDOORS.
UM, I HAVE A SCAR.
IT'S REALLY EMBARRASSING.
VERY WELL.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
OR SHOULD WE JUST CALL YOU
MANNERLESS COLONY SLOB?
[CHUCKLES]
JUST "SLOB" IS FINE.
OR, UH... KUZON.
[BELL TOLLS]
[STUDENTS TALKING]
[MOMO PURRS]
WE MADE IT THROUGH
THE DAY, MOMO...
AND IT WAS PRETTY FUN.
[PURRS]
DON'T LET THE HEADMASTER
CATCH YOU WITH THAT MONKEY.
WHAT MONKEY?
DON'T WORRY,
I'M NOT A TATTLETALE.
MY NAME'S ON JI.
I LIKE YOUR HEADBAND,
BY THE WAY.
ON JI, YOU DON'T HAVE
TO BABY-SIT THE NEW KID.
WOW.
YOU MUST BE ONE OF THOSE POPULAR
KIDS I'VE BEEN HEARING ABOUT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW LISTEN, FRIEND...
I KNOW YOU'RE FROM THE COLONIES
SO I'LL SAY THIS SLOWLY.
ON JI IS MY GIRLFRIEND.
DON'T FORGET IT.
IT WAS NICE MEETING YOU.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
HE DIDN'T BEAT YOU UP.
NOT EVEN A LITTLE.
I GUESS I'M JUST LUCKY.
WE WERE ON OUR WAY TO PLAY
HIDE AND EXPLODE.
YOU WANNA COME?
I'D LOVE TO.
Katara: WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WE'VE BEEN WORRIED SICK.
I GOT INVITED TO PLAY
WITH SOME KIDS AFTER SCHOOL.
Sokka: AFTER WHAT?
I ENROLLED IN
A FIRE NATION SCHOOL
AND I'M GOING BACK TOMORROW.
ENROLLED IN WHAT?
YOU AGAIN?
STOP WHERE YOU ARE.
Guard: PRINCE ZUKO?
[SWORD CLANKS]
AH!
I'M GOING IN FOR A VISIT.
YOU'RE GONNA STAND GUARD HERE
AND NO ONE IS GOING
TO KNOW ABOUT THIS.
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
UNCLE... IT'S ME.
AANG, I'M TRYING TO
BE MATURE AND NOT IMMEDIATELY
SHOOT DOWN YOUR IDEA.
BUT IT SOUNDS...
REALLY TERRIBLE.
YEAH, WE GOT OUR OUTFITS.
WHAT DO YOU NEED
TO GO TO SCHOOL FOR?
EVERY MINUTE
I'M IN THAT CLASSROOM
I'M LEARNING NEW THINGS
ABOUT THE FIRE NATION.
I ALREADY HAVE A PICTURE
OF FIRE LORD, OZAI.
AND HERE'S ONE THAT
I MADE OUT OF NOODLES.
IMPRESSIVE, I ADMIT.
BUT I STILL THINK
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
I GUESS WE'LL NEVER FIND OUT
ABOUT THE SECRET RIVER, THEN.
IT GOES RIGHT TO
THE FIRE LORD'S PALACE.
WE WERE SUPPOSED TO LEARN
ABOUT IT IN CLASS TOMORROW...
HMM... I AM A FAN
OF SECRET RIVERS.
FINE, LET'S STAY
A FEW MORE DAYS.
FLAMEY-O, HOTMAN.
FLAMEY-O?
[SHRUGS] UM-UM.
Zuko: YOU BROUGHT THIS
ON YOURSELF, YOU KNOW.
WE COULD HAVE RETURNED TOGETHER.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN A HERO.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT
TO JUDGE ME, UNCLE.
I DID WHAT I HAD TO DO
IN BA SING SE
AND YOU'RE A FOOL
FOR NOT JOINING ME.
YOU'RE NOT
GONNA SAY ANYTHING?
OH!
[YELLS]
YOU'RE A CRAZY OLD MAN.
YOU'RE CRAZY,
AND IF YOU WEREN'T IN JAIL
YOU'D BE SLEEPING
IN A GUTTER.
Teacher: GOOD MORNING, CLASS.
RECITE THE FIRE NATION OATH.
Students: MY LIFE,
I GIVE TO MY COUNTRY.
WITH MY HANDS,
I FIGHT FOR FIRE LORD...
Aang: FIRE LORD...
FOREFATHERS...
Students: WITH MY MIND, I SEEK
WAYS TO BETTER MY COUNTRY
AND WITH MY FEET...
Aang: FIREBENDERS...
FIRE LORD.
WHA, BAH,
BLAH, BLAH.
[STUDENTS CHUCKLING]
SINCE IT'S OBVIOUSLY HILARIOUS
TO MOCK OUR NATIONAL OATH
WE'LL BEGIN WITH A POP QUIZ ON
OUR GREAT MARCH OF CIVILIZATION.
[STUDENTS GROAN]
Teacher: QUESTION ONE.
WHAT YEAR DID FIRE LORD SOZIN
BATTLE THE AIR NATION ARMY?
KUZON?
Aang: IS THAT A TRICK QUESTION?
THE AIR NOMADS DIDN'T
HAVE A FORMAL MILITARY.
SOZIN DEFEATED THEM BY AMBUSH.
Teacher: WELL, I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU COULD POSSIBLY KNOW MORE
THAN OUR NATIONAL HISTORY BOOK
UNLESS YOU WERE THERE
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO.
I'LL JUST WRITE DOWN
MY BEST GUESS.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYS]
[PLAYS WRONG NOTES]
Music Teacher: KUZON?
[STOPS PLAYING]
I KNOW, I'M A TERRIBLE
TSUNGI HORNIST.
NO, CHILD.
THAT HULLABALOO GOING
ON WITH YOUR FEET.
IS THAT A NERVOUS DISORDER?
I WAS JUST DANCING.
YOU DO DANCES HERE IN THE
HOMELAND, RIGHT?
NOT REALLY, NO.
DANCING IS NOT CONDUCIVE TO
A PROPER LEARNING ENVIRONMENT.
YOUNG PEOPLE MUST HAVE RIGID
DISCIPLINE AND ORDER.
Aang: BUT WHAT ABOUT
EXPRESSING YOURSELF?
I KNOW SOMETIMES WE'RE SO MOVED
BY OUR LOVE FOR OUR NATION
THAT WE CAN'T CONTROL
OUR OWN BODIES.
IF YOU MUST
YOU MAY MARCH IN PLACE QUIETLY
NEXT TIME THE URGE HITS YOU.
[MUSIC RESUMES]
[ALL TALKING/WHISPERING]
OH, HI, KUZON.
I REALLY LIKED THAT CRAZY
DANCE YOU WERE DOING.
THANKS, ON JI.
I COULD SHOW IT TO YOU
AGAIN IF YOU'D LIKE.
AH!
WHAT'D YOU SAY,
COLONY TRASH?
YOU'RE GONNA SHOW HER SOMETHING?
JUST SOME
DANCE MOVEMENTS.
NOBODY SHOWS
MY ON JI ANYTHING
ESPECIALLY MOVEMENT.
[GRUNTS]
[AUDIBLE STRUGGLING...]
AH!
HA!
YAH!
AH.
[GRUNTS]
[SNIFFLES]
PICKING FIGHTS
ON YOUR SECOND DAY?
WE NEED TO HAVE A CONFERENCE
TO DISCUSS YOUR PUNISHMENT.
BRING YOUR PARENTS
TO MY OFFICE AFTER SCHOOL.
PARENTS, BUT...
DON'T BE LATE.
THANK YOU FOR COMING
MR. AND MRS...
FIRE... WANG FIRE.
THIS IS MY WIFE,
SAPPHIRE.
SAPPHIRE FIRE,
NICE TO MEET YOU.
MR. AND MRS. FIRE...
YOUR SON HAS BEEN ENROLLED
HERE FOR TWO DAYS
AND HE'S ALREADY
CAUSING PROBLEMS.
HE'S ARGUED WITH
HIS HISTORY TEACHER
DISRUPTED MUSIC CLASS
AND ROUGHED UP MY STAR PUPIL.
MY GOODNESS.
THAT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE OUR KUZON.
THAT'S WHAT ANY MOTHER
WOULD SAY, MA'AM.
NONETHELESS,
YOU'RE FOREWARNED.
IF HE ACTS UP
ONE MORE TIME
I'LL HAVE HIM SENT
TO REFORM SCHOOL...
BY WHICH I MEAN THE COAL MINES.
ARE WE CLEAR?
DON'T YOU WORRY,
MR. HEADMASTER
I'LL STRAIGHTEN THIS BOY
OUT SOMETHING FIERCE.
YOUNG MAN, AS SON AS WE GET
HOME, YOU'RE GONNA GET THE
PUNISHMENT OF A LIFETIME.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE TO HEAR.
Mai: ORANGE IS SUCH
AN AWFUL COLOR.
[SNICKERS]
YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL
WHEN YOU HATE THE WORLD.
I DON'T HATE YOU.
I DON'T HATE YOU, TOO.
[AZULA CLEARS THROAT]
ZUKO, COULD I HAVE
A WORD WITH YOU?
CAN'T YOU SEE WE'RE BUSY?
OH, MAI, TY LEE NEEDS YOUR HELP
UNTANGLING HER BRAID.
SOUNDS PRETTY SERIOUS.
SO I HEAR YOU'VE BEEN
TO VISIT YOUR UNCLE FATSO
IN THE PRISON TOWER.
THAT GUARD TOLD YOU.
NO, YOU DID... JUST NOW.
OK, YOU CAUGHT ME.
WHAT IS IT THAT
YOU WANT, AZULA.
ACTUALLY, NOTHING.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
I'M LOOKING OUT FOR YOU.
IF PEOPLE FIND OUT
YOU'VE BEEN TO SEE UNCLE
THEY'LL THINK YOU'RE
PLOTTING WITH HIM.
JUST BE CAREFUL DUM-DUM.
[BIRDS SQUAWK]
THAT SETTLES IT.
NO MORE SCHOOL FOR YOU,
YOUNG MAN.
Aang: I'M NOT
READY TO LEAVE.
I'M HAVING FUN FOR ONCE
JUST BEING A NORMAL KID.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE, SOKKA.
YOU GET TO BE NORMAL
ALL THE TIME.
HA, HA.
LISTEN, GUYS, THOSE KIDS
AT SCHOOL ARE THE FUTURE
OF THE FIRE NATION.
IF WE WANNA CHANGE
THIS PLACE FOR THE BETTER
WE NEED TO SHOW THEM
A LITTLE TASTE OF FREEDOM.
WHAT COULD YOU POSSIBLY DO
FOR A COUNTRY OF DEPRAVED
LITTLE FIRE MONSTERS?
I'M GONNA THROW THEM
A SECRET DANCE PARTY.
GO TO YOUR ROOM.
I CAN'T BELIEVE WE'RE
HAVING A DANCE PARTY.
IT SEEMS SO... SILLY.
DON'T THINK OF IT
AS A DANCE PARTY
BUT AS A CULTURAL EVENT
CELEBRATING THE ART
OF FANCY FOOTWORK.
THEY'RE COMING.
EVERYONE STOP BENDING.
Aang: SORRY, BUDDY.
YOU SHOULD PROBABLY
WAIT OUT BACK.
[GROWLS]
Aang: I KNOW, YOU'VE GOT
FANCIER FEET THAN ANYBODY...
AND SIX OF 'EM.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
Aang: LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THE FLAMEY-Os!
YEAH, THIS OUGHT TO GET
EVERYBODY MOVING.
NOW WHAT
DO WE DO?
THIS IS WHEN YOU START DANCING.
I DON'T THINK
MY PARENTS WANT ME
DANCING IN A CAVE.
YEAH, WHAT IF SOMEONE
FINDS OUT?
OH, BOY.
LISTEN, GUYS...
DANCING ISN'T SOMETHING
YOU THINK ABOUT.
IT'S A FORM OF SELF-EXPRESSION
THAT NO ONE CAN EVER
TAKE AWAY FROM YOU.
MAYBE IT WAS DIFFERENT
IN THE COLONIES, KUZON,
BUT WE DON'T DO THAT HERE.
SURE YOU DO.
YOU HAVE FOR GENERATIONS.
IT JUST SO HAPPENS
THAT I KNOW SEVERAL CLASSIC
FIRE NATION DANCES.
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO
THIS WAS KNOWN AS
"THE PHOENIX FLIGHT."
Students: OOH... WOW.
AND THIS WAS
THE "CAMELEPHANT STRUT".
[GIGGLING]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
WHO KNEW TWINKLE TOES
COULD DANCE?
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
I BROUGHT YOU SOME
KOMODO-CHICKEN.
I KNOW YOU DON'T CARE FOR IT
BUT I FIGURE
IT BEATS PRISON FOOD.
I ADMIT IT.
I HAVE EVERYTHING
I ALWAYS WANTED
BUT IT'S NOT AT ALL HOW
I THOUGHT IT WOULD BE.
THE TRUTH IS I NEED YOUR ADVICE.
I THINK THE AVATAR
IS STILL ALIVE.
I KNOW HE'S OUT THERE.
I'M LOSING MY MIND.
PLEASE, UNCLE, I'M SO CONFUSED,
I NEED YOUR HELP.
FORGET IT.
I'LL SOLVE THIS MYSELF.
WASTE AWAY IN HERE
FOR ALL I CARE.
[DOOR CREAKS SHUT]
[DANCE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
AND THIS IS HOW THEY DO IT IN
THE BALLROOMS OF BA SING SE.
WOW, THEY LOOK PRETTY
GOOD TOGETHER.
EH, IF THAT'S WHAT YOU LIKE.
Aang: YEAH, THAT'S IT.
THAT'S THE SOUND OF HAPPY FEET.
ALL RIGHT, GO WITH THAT.
EVERYBODY, FREESTYLE.
I DON'T KNOW, AANG.
THESE SHOES AREN'T
REALLY RIGHT FOR DANCING
AND I'M NOT SURE
THAT I KNOW HOW TO...
TAKE MY HAND.
OK.
AANG, EVERYONE'S WATCHING.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THEM.
IT'S JUST YOU AND ME RIGHT NOW.
[STUDENTS GASP]
Student: WOW.
[MUSIC ENDS]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[PANTING]
[FAINT CHEERING]
IT IS A DANCING PARTY.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING BY
TELLING ME, HIDE.
ANYTIME,
HEADMASTER, SIR.
THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
IT'S LIKE MY INHIBITIONS
JUST DISAPPEAR.
OK, THEY'RE BACK AGAIN.
Headmaster: HE'S
THE ONE WE WANT.
THE BOY WITH THE HEADBAND.
UH-OH.
Guard: GOT YA.
LOOKING FOR ME?
THAT'S NOT THE ONE.
HE'S HERE SOMEWHERE.
DON'T LET HIM LEAVE THE CAVE.
YES?
HI THERE.
HOW WE DOING?
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE?
WHO ARE YOU
LOOKING FOR?
DO YOU NEED SOMETHING?
OVER HERE.
STOP THAT.
WE'RE SAFE, SOKKA.
YOU CAN TAKE OFF
THE MOUSTACHE, NOW.
OH, NO, I CAN'T.
IT'S PERMANENTLY
GLUED TO MY SKIN.
WAY TO GO, DANCY PANTS.
I THINK YOU REALLY
DID HELP THOSE KIDS.
YOU TAUGHT THEM TO BE FREE.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS JUST
A DANCE PARTY, THAT'S ALL.
WELL, THAT WAS SOME
DANCE PARTY, AANG.
MWAH.
FLAMEY-O, SIR...
FLAMEY-O.
[BIRDS CAWING]
[GATE OPENS]
YOU'RE SURE
YOU WEREN'T FOLLOWED?
Zuko: I'VE HEARD ABOUT YOU.
THEY SAY YOU'RE GOOD
AT WHAT YOU DO
AND EVEN BETTER
AT KEEPING SECRETS.
THE AVATAR'S ALIVE.
I WANT YOU TO FIND HIM
AND END HIM.
♪