Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO...
THE FOUR NATIONS LIVED
TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST
HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED AND MY BROTHER
AND I DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS WERE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
EVER SINCE YOU JOINED US,
YOU'VE BEEN NOTHING
BUT SELFISH AND UNHELPFUL.
WHAT?
LOOK HERE, SUGAR QUEEN.
I GAVE UP EVERYTHING I HAD
SO THAT I COULD
TEACH AANG EARTHBENDING
SO DON'T YOU TALK TO ME
ABOUT BEING SELFISH.
THE AVATAR IS ALIVE.
I WANT YOU TO FIND HIM,
AND END HIM.
Sokka: THIS IS CRAZY.
HOW CAN I BEAT A GUY WHO
BLOWS THINGS UP WITH HIS MIND?
Aang: YOU CAN'T.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
HOW COULD YOU DO THIS TO ME?
YOU BETRAYED ME.
YOU BROUGHT THIS ON YOURSELF.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
OK, I'M READY FOR SOME TRAINING.
GOOD JOB, TWINKLE-TOES.
VISUALIZE, THEN ATTACK.
[KATARA GRUNTING]
MAYBE YOU SHOULD TAKE
YOUR OWN ADVICE, TOPH.
Toph: WHAT'S THE MATTER?
CAN'T HANDLE SOME DIRT,
MADAME FUSSY BRITCHES?
OH, SORRY, DID I SPLASH YOU,
MUD SLUG?
[GRUNTING]
ARE WE TAKING A BREAK?
[SCREAMING]
SNEAK ATTACK!
[GRUNTING]
SOKKA, SNEAK ATTACKS DON'T WORK
IF YOU YELL IT OUT LOUD.
[GRUNTING]
HUNGRY FOR A MUD PIE?
I'LL GIVE YOU A MUD PIE.
[GRUNTING]
UH, GUYS, I THOUGHT WE WERE
SUPPOSED TO BE TRAINING ME.
VERY WELL, PUPIL.
I BELIEVE WE'VE HAD
ENOUGH TRAINING FOR TODAY.
WHILE KATARA CLEANS UP,
LET'S GO HAVE SOME FUN.
YES!
YEAH!
[BIRD SQUAWKING]
Sokka: LOOK AT ALL
THOSE MESSENGER HAWKS.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT GETTING ONE FOR MYSELF.
THAT WAY, I WOULDN'T
HAVE TO TALK TO ANYONE.
I COULD JUST SEND THEM MESSAGES.
I GOT TO SAY, I LIKE THE IDEA
OF NOT TALKING TO YOU.
SO, GUYS, WHAT ARE WE GONNA GET
WITH OUR LAST SILVER PIECE?
WE CAN GET MORE MONEY.
RIGHT THERE.
THIS IS WHERE YOU SEEING PEOPLE
ARE AT A DISADVANTAGE.
EVERYONE GUESSES WRONG BECAUSE
THE DEALER MOVES THE ROCK
AT THE LAST MINUTE
BUT I CAN FEEL IT
WITH MY EARTHBENDING.
[GASPING]
[CRYING]
YOU THERE.
WANT TO PLAY A FRIENDLY GAME?
HOW COULD I POSSIBLY PLAY?
I'M BLIND.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SEE
TO BE LUCKY.
"FLAMEY-O," TOPH.
Dealer: WOW, FANCY GUESSING.
YOU ARE AMAZING AT THIS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO MAKE THE GAME
A LITTLE MORE INTERESTING?
MORE INTERESTING?
HOW?
WELL, LET'S SAY YOU TOSS IN
YOUR FRIEND'S FINE SWORD THERE.
THEN I'LL PUT UP
20 SILVER PIECES AGAINST IT,
AND THAT'S MORE INTERESTING.
I'LL DO IT FOR 40 SILVER PIECES.
[GASPING]
FORTY SILVER PIECES IT IS.
SORRY, LITTLE LADY, BUT...
HUH?
I WON!
[LAUGHING]
WHERE DID YOU GUYS GET THE MONEY
TO BUY ALL THIS STUFF?
TOPH GOT US MONEY.
SHE SCAMMED ONE OF THOSE GUYS
IN TOWN WHO MOVES THE SHELLS
AROUND ALL SNEAKY-LIKE.
SHE USED EARTHBENDING
TO WIN THE GAME.
CLASSIC.
- AH, SO SHE CHEATED.
HEY, I ONLY CHEATED
BECAUSE HE WAS CHEATING.
I CHEATED A CHEATER.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT?
I'M JUST SAYING,
THIS ISN'T SOMETHING
WE SHOULD MAKE A HABIT OF DOING.
WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S FUN,
AND YOU HATE FUN?
I DON'T HATE FUN.
SEE?
FUN.
[SQUEAKING]
KATARA, I'LL PERSONALLY MAKE YOU
AN AVATAR PROMISE
THAT WE WON'T MAKE A HABIT
OF DOING THESE SCAMS.
GUYS, I THINK THESE SCAMS
HAVE GONE FAR ENOUGH.
IF YOU KEEP DOING THEM,
SOMETHING BAD IS GONNA HAPPEN.
COULD YOU FOR ONCE
STOP BEING SUCH A SOURPUSS
AND JUST LIGHTEN UP?
OH, I'M SORRY.
YOU THINK I SHOULD
BE MORE LIKE YOU?
LIKE SOME WILD CHILD?
YEAH, MAYBE.
MAYBE THEN, YOU'D SEE
HOW GREAT WE HAVE IT.
I MEAN, LOOK AT US.
WE'RE TRAVELING AROUND
THE WORLD, MAKING EASY MONEY
HAVING FUN, WITH NO PARENTS
TO TELL US WHAT TO DO.
AH, I SEE.
YOU'RE ACTING LIKE THIS
BECAUSE OF YOUR PARENTS.
WHATEVER.
THEY WERE CONTROLLING OVER YOU,
SO YOU RAN AWAY, AND NOW YOU ACT
LIKE YOUR PARENTS DON'T EXIST.
YOU ACT LIKE YOU HATE THEM,
BUT YOU DON'T.
YOU JUST FEEL GUILTY.
I DO HATE THEM.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK YOU MISS THEM.
BUT YOU JUST DON'T WANT
TO DEAL WITH THAT, SO INSTEAD,
YOU ACT LIKE THIS CRAZY PERSON.
LOOK, I RAN AWAY TO HELP AANG.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THESE SCAMS PUT US ALL AT RISK,
AND WE DON'T NEED THAT.
WE'VE ALREADY GOT
SOME THIRD-EYED FREAK AFTER US.
SPEAKING OF
THAT THIRD-EYED FREAK
I THINK I'VE COME UP
WITH A NAME FOR HIM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
"SPARKY-SPARKY BOOM MAN"?
JUST THINK ABOUT IT.
WE HAVE ENOUGH MONEY.
YOU NEED TO STOP THIS.
I'LL STOP WHEN I WANT TO STOP,
AND NOT WHEN YOU TELL ME.
[SQUEAKING]
SPEAKING OF MONEY,
I'M OFF TO SPEND SOME.
SEE YOU GUYS LATER.
HAWKY, WELCOME TO TEAM AVATAR.
MY NAME'S SOKKA,
AND I'M YOUR NEW OWNER
AND AS SUCH I SHOULD WARN YOU
THAT THERE'S ALREADY
A LEMUR IN OUR GROUP
SO I DON'T WANT
TO SEE ANY FIGHTING.
[SQUAWKING]
GOOD "WITTLE" MESSENGER HAWKY.
WHO'S GOT PRETTY FEATHERS?
[SQUAWKING]
[GASPING]
YOU'RE RIGHT, HAWKY.
THIS IS BAD.
TOPH, WHEN I WAS IN TOWN,
I FOUND SOMETHING
THAT YOU'RE NOT GONNA LIKE.
WELL, IT SOUNDS LIKE
A SHEET OF PAPER
BUT I GUESS YOU'RE REFERRING
TO WHAT'S ON THE SHEET OF PAPER.
IT'S A WANTED POSTER, OF YOU.
THEY'VE NICKNAMED YOU
"THE RUNAWAY."
A WANTED POSTER.
THAT'S SO GREAT.
THE RUNAWAY.
I LOVE MY NEW NICKNAME.
IS THERE A PICTURE OF ME?
DOES IT LOOK GOOD?
WELL, YEAH, ACTUALLY,
IT DOES LOOK PRETTY GOOD.
BUT TOPH,
YOU'RE MISSING THE POINT.
MAYBE KATARA WAS RIGHT.
THESE SCAMS ARE DRAWING
TOO MUCH ATTENTION TO US.
DON'T BE SUCH A WORRYWART
LIKE YOUR SISTER.
THINK OF IT THIS WAY.
NOW YOU HAVE PLENTY OF MONEY
TO HELP WITH THE INVASION PLAN.
WELL, THAT IS TRUE.
I HAD THIS IDEA
OF MAKING ARMOR FOR APPA.
[GROWLING]
HERE'S A LITTLE EXTRA
SO YOU CAN GET YOURSELF
A NICE MAP OF THE FIRE NATION.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
MAKE IT AN ATLAS.
I DO LIKE EXPENSIVE ATLASES.
OF COURSE YOU DO, AND THAT'S WHY
THIS WANTED POSTER IS GOING
TO STAY OUR LITTLE SECRET.
SOKKA, TELL ME
YOU DIDN'T BUY A BIRD.
NOT JUST A BIRD.
A MESSENGER BIRD.
NOW WE CAN SEND MESSAGES
ALL OVER THE WORLD,
EVEN TO GRAN-GRAN.
WOW, HOW DOES IT WORK?
HM, UH, I NEVER ACTUALLY
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT.
HAWKY, GRAN-GRAN, SOUTH POLE.
[SQUAWKING]
I THINK HE GETS IT.
[SQUEALING]
HAWKY, MAKE NICE.
BAD HAWKY.
[GROWLING]
WELL, LOOK WHO DECIDED
TO JOIN US.
WHERE HAVE YOU TWO BEEN?
OFF SCAMMING AGAIN?
YES, WE WERE.
AND I SUPPOSE YOU DON'T THINK
WHAT YOU'RE DOING
IS DANGEROUS AT ALL?
NO, I DON'T.
REALLY?
YES, REALLY.
WELL THEN, WHAT'S THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
WHAT'S WITH YOU PEOPLE?
I'M BLIND.
IT'S A WANTED POSTER OF YOU.
THE RUNAWAY.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE CALLED NOW?
ARE YOU PROUD OF THIS?
WHERE DID YOU GET THAT?
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHERE I GOT IT.
- THE FACT IS--
- YOU WENT THROUGH MY STUFF.
YOU HAD NO RIGHT.
YOUR STUFF WAS MESSY,
AND I WAS JUST STRAIGHTENING UP
AND I HAPPENED
TO STUMBLE ACROSS IT.
THAT'S A LIE.
YOU'RE LYING, KATARA.
FINE, IT'S A LIE,
BUT YOU'VE BEEN SO
OUT OF CONTROL LATELY
I KNEW SOMETHING WAS UP.
I KNEW YOU WERE
HIDING SOMETHING, AND YOU WERE.
DON'T YOU WALK AWAY FROM ME
WHILE I'M TALKING TO YOU.
- OH, REALLY, MOM?
OR WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
SEND ME TO MY ROOM?
I WISH I COULD.
WELL, YOU CAN'T,
BECAUSE YOU'RE NOT MY MOM
AND YOU'RE NOT THEIR MOM.
I NEVER SAID I WAS.
NO, BUT YOU CERTAINLY
ACT LIKE IT.
YOU THINK IT'S YOUR JOB
TO BOSS EVERYONE AROUND,
BUT IT'S NOT.
YOU'RE JUST A REGULAR KID LIKE
THE REST OF US, SO STOP ACTING
LIKE YOU CAN TELL ME WHAT TO DO.
I CAN DO WHATEVER I WANT.
I DON'T ACT THAT WAY.
SOKKA, DO I ACT MOTHERLY?
HEY, I'M STAYING
OUT OF THIS ONE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, AANG?
DO I ACT LIKE A MOM?
WELL, I...
STOP RUBBING YOUR EYE
AND SPEAK CLEARLY WHEN YOU TALK.
YES, MA'AM.
I CAN'T BE AROUND YOU RIGHT NOW.
WELL, I CAN'T BE AROUND YOU.
[SQUAWKING]
I KNOW, HAWKY.
WHY CAN'T THEY JUST GET ALONG?
HEY, AANG, YOU WANT TO TEST OUT
MY MESSENGER HAWK WITH ME?
I'VE GOT AN IDEA.
SURE.
I'M GONNA SEND A NOTE TO KATARA
AND SAY IT'S FROM TOPH,
WHO WANTS TO APOLOGIZE.
THEN EVERYONE
WILL BE FRIENDS AGAIN.
I GOT TO SAY, SOKKA,
YOU CONTINUE TO IMPRESS ME
WITH YOUR IDEAS.
EH, IT'S A GIFT.
DEAR KATARA.
SORRY FOR EVERYTHING.
YOUR FRIEND, TOPH.
[SQUAWKING]
Katara: I KNOW THIS IS
FROM YOU, SOKKA.
TOPH CAN'T WRITE.
UGH, YOU'RE ALL
DRIVING ME CRAZY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE WE FORGOT
TOPH CAN'T WRITE.
YEP, WE'RE IDIOTS.
I GUESS PLAN B IS,
WE SEND A NOTE TO TOPH
PRETENDING IT'S FROM KATARA.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA RUN INTO
A SIMILAR PROBLEM.
[SQUAWKING]
SORRY, HAWKY.
LOOKS LIKE I'M GONNA HAVE TO
DO THIS WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
COME ON, WE NEED TO TALK.
SO LET ME GUESS.
YOU BROUGHT ME OUT HERE
TO TELL ME YOUR SISTER'S
NOT AS ANNOYING AS
I MAKE HER OUT TO BE.
NAH, SHE'S PRETTY MUCH A PAIN.
SHE'S ALWAYS GOT
TO BE RIGHT ABOUT EVERYTHING
AND SHE GETS ALL BOSSY,
AND INVOLVED,
AND IN YOUR BUSINESS.
Toph: YEAH, I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU CAN DEAL WITH IT.
Sokka: ACTUALLY, IN A WAY,
I RELY ON IT.
Toph: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHEN OUR MOM DIED, THAT WAS
THE HARDEST TIME IN MY LIFE.
OUR FAMILY WAS A MESS,
BUT KATARA,
SHE HAD SO MUCH STRENGTH.
SHE STEPPED UP AND TOOK ON
SO MUCH RESPONSIBILITY.
SHE HELPED FILL THE VOID
THAT WAS LEFT BY OUR MOM.
I GUESS I NEVER
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU
SOMETHING CRAZY.
I NEVER TOLD ANYONE THIS BEFORE
BUT HONESTLY,
I'M NOT SURE I CAN REMEMBER
WHAT MY MOTHER LOOKED LIKE.
IT REALLY SEEMS LIKE,
MY WHOLE LIFE, KATARA'S BEEN
THE ONE LOOKING OUT FOR ME.
SHE'S ALWAYS BEEN THE ONE
THAT'S THERE, AND NOW
WHEN I TRY TO REMEMBER
MY MOM, KATARA'S IS
THE ONLY FACE I CAN PICTURE.
Toph: THE TRUTH IS, SOMETIMES
KATARA DOES ACT MOTHERLY, BUT
THAT'S NOT ALWAYS A BAD THING.
SHE'S COMPASSIONATE AND KIND,
AND SHE ACTUALLY CARES ABOUT ME.
YOU KNOW, THE REAL ME.
THAT'S MORE THAN MY OWN MOM.
DON'T EVER TELL HER
I SAID ANY OF THIS.
HEY, MY LIPS ARE SEALED.
[PURRING]
HI, TOPH.
UM, I WANT TO...
KATARA, STOP.
YOU DON'T NEED TO APOLOGIZE.
I WAS THE ONE BEING STUPID.
THESE SCAMS ARE OUT OF CONTROL,
AND I'M DONE WITH THEM.
ACTUALLY, I WASN'T GOING
TO APOLOGIZE.
I WAS GONNA SAY,
I WANT TO PULL A SCAM WITH YOU.
WHAT?
YOU WANT TO PULL A SCAM?
NOT JUST ANY SCAM.
THE ULTIMATE SCAM.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, TOPH?
JUST ME AND YOU.
ONE LAST GO.
YOU IN?
YOU KNOW I'M IN.
NOW WHAT'S THIS IDEA OF YOURS?
[GROANING]
THE PLAN IS SIMPLE.
THIS WANTED POSTER SAYS
YOU'RE WORTH A LOT OF MONEY
10 TIMES MORE THAN
YOU'VE MADE IN ALL YOUR SCAMS
SO I'M GONNA TURN YOU IN
AND COLLECT THE REWARD.
THEN YOU METALBEND YOURSELF
OUT OF JAIL,
AND WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
HOW COULD YOU DO THIS TO ME?
YOU BETRAYED ME.
YOU BROUGHT THIS ON YOURSELF.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING
BY TURNING IN THE RUNAWAY.
THE RIGHT THING
IS ITS OWN REWARD.
WELL, I'M HAPPY
TO HEAR YOU SAY THAT.
BUT I STILL WANT
THE ACTUAL REWARD.
OF COURSE.
RIGHT THIS WAY.
HEY, WHAT KIND OF CELL IS THIS?
A WOODEN ONE.
THAT'S HER. THAT'S THE GIRL
YOU WERE LOOKING FOR.
DO YOU THINK THIS SCAM OF THEIRS
SHOULD BE TAKING THIS LONG?
I WAS JUST WONDERING
THE SAME THING.
WE'D BETTER CHECK IT OUT.
[SQUAWKING]
YOU TWO BEHAVE.
APPA'S IN CHARGE.
[GROWLING]
[SQUAWKING]
WAIT, IT'S A TRAP.
REALLY?
NO KIDDING.
IS THAT WHY WE'RE SITTING
IN A WOODEN CAGE RIGHT NOW?
GEE, HOW'D YOU FIGURE OUT
IT WAS A TRAP?
NOT FOR US, KATARA.
WE'RE THE BAIT.
HE WANTS AANG.
[SIGHING]
I CAN'T BELIEVE I WAS SO STUPID.
SEE, THIS IS EXACTLY WHY
I'M AGAINST THESE SCAMS.
I KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
BUT THIS WAS YOUR IDEA.
I KNOW.
I WANTED TO SHOW YOU
THAT I'M NOT SO MOTHERLY.
THAT I CAN HAVE FUN TOO.
KATARA, YOU ARE FUN.
IF NOTHING ELSE, YOU'RE AT LEAST
FUN TO ARGUE WITH.
I KNOW YOUR RELATIONSHIP WITH
YOUR PARENTS IS COMPLICATED
AND I SHOULDN'T HAVE SAID
WHAT I SAID.
IT'S OK.
I WAS REALLY MAD
WHEN YOU SAID THAT BECAUSE,
WELL, BECAUSE MAYBE IT'S TRUE.
I TRY NOT TO THINK ABOUT IT,
BUT WHEN I LEFT,
I PROBABLY REALLY HURT THEM.
[SNIFFLES]
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THEY MIGHT BE?
WHERE DO YOU THINK ANYONE IS?
[INHALING DEEPLY]
Aang: SOKKA, WATCH OUT.
[SOKKA SHRIEKING]
IT'S SPARKY-SPARKY BOOM MAN.
YOU KNOW, I'M STARTING TO THINK
THAT NAME DOESN'T QUITE FIT.
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
I WISH WE HAD
SOME EARTH OR WATER.
WE NEED BENDABLES.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR METEOR BRACELET?
YOU COULD MAKE A SAW.
I LEFT IT BACK AT CAMP.
I WAS WORRIED
THEY WOULD TAKE IT.
[SIGHING]
UM, KATARA?
ARE YOU OK?
JUST FINE.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M MAKING MY OWN WATER.
KATARA, YOU'RE A GENIUS.
A SWEATY, STINKY GENIUS.
[GRUNTING]
THIS GUY IS TOO GOOD.
HE SHOOTS FIRE FROM HIS BRAIN.
WE SHOULD SPLIT UP.
HE CAN'T CHASE US BOTH.
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
AANG, GET UP.
Toph: LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[GROWLING]
[GRUNTING]
HEY, I GOT IT.
THE PERFECT NAME FOR THAT GUY.
COMBUSTION MAN.
GOOD JOB, SOKKA.
NOW LET'S GET OUT OF HERE BEFORE
COMBUSTION MAN CATCHES US.
Sokka: SEE?
IT FITS SO WELL.
[APPA GROWLING]
WELL, I'M EXHAUSTED.
HAWKY, HOW ABOUT YOU, BUDDY?
YEAH, YOU'RE SUCH
A LAZY LITTLE BIRD.
KATARA, I NEED YOUR HELP.
WHAT IS IT, TOPH?
I NEED YOU TO WRITE
SOME THINGS DOWN FOR ME.
I WANT TO SEND
A LETTER TO MY PARENTS.
I'LL BE HAPPY TO HELP.
Sokka: HEY, WHERE'D HAWKY GO?
♪ [MEN VOCALIZING
RHYTHMICALLY] ♪