Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED
AND MY BROTHER AND I DISCOVERED
THE NEW AVATAR...
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Ozai: YOU HAVE REDEEMED
YOURSELF, MY SON.
WELCOME HOME.
I KNOW ONE THING I CARE ABOUT.
I CARE ABOUT YOU.
Sokka: A SOLAR ECLIPSE
IS COMING.
THE SUN WILL BE ENTIRELY
BLOCKED OUT BY THE MOON
AND THE FIREBENDERS
WILL BE HELPLESS.
THAT'S THE DAY WE NEED TO INVADE
THE FIRE NATION.
THE DAY OF BLACK SUN.
I'VE ALWAYS KNOWN THAT I WOULD
HAVE TO FACE THE FIRE LORD.
BUT NOW I KNOW
I NEED TO DO IT ALONE.
♪
[APPA GROANS]
[MOMO CHATTERS]
THIS IS IT, THE OFFICIAL
RENDEZVOUS POINT
FOR THE INVASION FORCE.
Toph: HOW DID YOU PICK
THIS PLACE?
Sokka: BEFORE WE SPLIT UP,
MY DAD AND I FOUND THIS ISLAND
ON A MAP.
IT'S UNINHABITED, AND THE HARBOR
SURROUNDED BY CLIFFS SEEMED LIKE
THE PERFECT SECLUDED PLACE.
Katara: NICE CHOICE, SOKKA.
AND WE'RE HERE FOUR DAYS
AHEAD OF SCHEDULE.
WAIT, FOUR DAYS?
THE INVASION'S IN FOUR DAYS?
[YAWNS]
WHATEVER, THAT'S, LIKE,
FOUR DAYS FROM NOW.
LET'S JUST CALM DOWN AND...
[SNORING...]
SOKKA'S GOT THE RIGHT
IDEA, AANG.
WE'RE HERE, WE'RE READY.
THE BEST THING WE CAN DO NOW
IS GET PLENTY OF REST.
[GROANS] I GUESS.
Aang: YOUR DAYS OF TYRANNY
ARE OVER, FIRE LORD.
I'M BRINGING YOU DOWN.
REALLY?
HOW DO YOU PLAN ON DOING THAT
WHEN YOU'RE NOT EVEN
WEARING PANTS?
[YELLS]
OH, NO.
[CACKLING...]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
[SIGHS]
[MOMO CHATTERS]
IT WAS JUST A DREAM, MOMO.
I STILL HAVE MY PANTS.
[CHATTERING]
WELL, I BETTER KEEP TRAINING.
[CHATTERS]
FRESH FRUIT, PRINCE ZUKO?
MAY I WASH YOUR FEET, SIR?
HEAD MASSAGE?
HOT TOWEL?
[CROWD CHEERING...]
[GIRLS LAUGHING...]
[LAUGHING]
OH...
PRINCE ZUKO, IS SOMETHING WRONG?
YOU DIDN'T TAKE THE PALANQUIN.
I'M JUST GOING TO MAI'S HOUSE,
IT'S NOT FAR.
IT'S NOT A PRINCE'S PLACE
TO WALK ANYWHERE, SIR.
[THUDDING...]
HEY, HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN UP?
A COUPLE HOURS.
I GOT A LOT MORE SKILLS TO
REFINE IF I'M GONNA FIGHT OZAI.
Katara: YOU KNOW, THERE IS
SUCH A THING AS OVERTRAINING.
[GRUNTING]
YOU DON'T GET IT, DO YOU?
MY FORM IS BAD, I'M SLOPPY,
AND I STILL DON'T KNOW
ANY FIREBENDING.
NOT EVEN THE BASICS.
THAT'S OK, AANG,
THE ECLIPSE WILL BLOCK
ALL FIREBENDING ANYWAY.
YOU DON'T NEED TO KNOW ANY.
PLUS, IT'S A STUPID ELEMENT.
OK, WELL, I STILL HAVE TO
WORK ON EVERYTHING ELSE.
I BETTER SPEND
THE WHOLE DAY TRAINING.
[YAWNS]
GOOD NIGHT, KATARA.
GOOD NIGHT, SOKKA.
GOOD NIGHT, TOPH.
GOOD NIGHT, APPA,
GOOD NIGHT, MOMO.
GOOD NIGHT, APPA AND MO...
GO TO SLEEP, ALREADY.
[SNAPS FINGERS]
YOUR DAYS OF TYRANNY
ARE OVER, FIRE LORD.
I'M BRINGING YOU DOWN.
AND THIS TIME I BROUGHT PANTS.
SO IT SEEMS.
BUT ARE YOU PREPARED
FOR YOUR MATHEMATICS TEST?
MATH TEST?
OH, NO, I FORGOT ALL ABOUT
THE MATH TEST.
[OZAI CACKLING]
[AANG SCREAMS]
[GASPING]
I'VE GOT TO BE READY.
AANG, IT'S THE MIDDLE
OF THE NIGHT.
YOU NEED TO GO BACK TO SLEEP.
BUT I FORGOT MY PANTS
AND MY MATH TEST.
[SIGHS]
AANG, SLEEP.
PLEASE, FOR ME.
[SHEEP BAAS]
TELL ME, IF YOU COULD HAVE
ANYTHING YOU WANTED RIGHT NOW
WHAT WOULD IT BE?
HMM... A BIG FANCY FRUIT TART
WITH ROSE PETALS ON TOP.
YOU KNOW, BEING A PRINCE
AND ALL, I MIGHT JUST
BE ABLE TO MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
[LAUGHS] THAT WOULD
BE IMPRESSIVE.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN FIND
A FRESH FRUIT TART FOR THE LADY?
WITH ROSE PETALS ON TOP?
EXCELLENT CHOICE, SIR.
I GUESS THERE ARE SOME
NICE PERKS THAT COME WITH
BEING ROYALTY.
THOUGH THERE'S
ANNOYING STUFF TOO.
LIKE THAT ALL-DAY WAR MEETING
COMING UP.
WAR MEETING,
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
AZULA MENTIONED SOMETHING.
I, I ASSUMED YOU WERE GOING TOO.
I GUESS I WASN'T INVITED.
Ozai: WAKE UP, AANG.
WAKE UP, SLEEPYHEAD.
RISE AND SHINE.
YOU OVERSLEPT.
YOU MISSED THE INVASION.
[CACKLING...]
SOKKA, GET UP, I NEED TO KNOW
WHAT DAY IT IS.
WHAT, WHO'S TALKING?
OW.
RELAX, IT'S STILL TWO DAYS
BEFORE THE INVASION.
SOKKA, YOU'VE GOT TO GET UP
AND DRILL YOUR
ROCK-CLIMBING EXERCISES.
WHAT?
IN ONE OF MY DREAMS,
YOU WERE RUNNING FROM
FIRE NATION SOLDIERS
TRYING TO CLIMB THIS CLIFF
BUT YOU WERE TOO SLOW
AND THEY GOT YOU.
BUT THAT WAS JUST A DREAM,
I'M A GREAT CLIMBER.
THEN CLIMB THAT CLIFF,
CLIMB IT FAST.
STUPID AVATAR, STUPID CLIFF,
STUPID DREAM.
I CAN CLIMB FAST.
DON'T DRINK THAT!
[SOKKA SCREAMS]
WHY, IS IT POISONED?
IN MY DREAM, WE WERE RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE INVASION
AND YOU HAD TO STOP
TO USE THE BATHROOM.
WE DIED BECAUSE OF YOUR
TINY BLADDER.
AND YOU NEED TO START
WEARING YOUR HAIR UP.
IN MY DREAM, YOUR HAIR
GOT CAUGHT IN A TRAIN AND...
AANG, I KNOW YOU'RE JUST
TRYING TO HELP.
BUT YOU REALLY NEED TO
GET A GRIP.
YOU'RE UNRAVELING.
[SIGHS]
YOU'RE RIGHT,
I'M LOSING MY MIND.
[SCREAMS]
IT'S LIKE EVERY TIME
I THINK ABOUT HOW STRESSED I AM
I JUST END UP MORE STRESSED.
I'M LIKE A BIG GROWING SNOWBALL
OF NERVES.
OF COURSE YOU ARE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE YOU GOTTA FIGHT
THE FIRE LORD, THE BADDEST MAN
ON THE PLANET.
AND YOU BETTER WIN,
OR WE'RE ALL DONE FOR.
SOKKA, YOU'RE NOT HELPING.
WHAT?
IT'S TRUE, THAT'S THE DEAL,
HE KNOWS IT.
[WHIMPERING]
YOU KNOW WHAT,
I'VE GOT JUST THE THING.
GET READY TO BE DE-STRESSIFIED.
...THESE YOGA STRETCHES
CAN REALLY WORK WONDERS
IF YOU DO THEM IN EXTREME HEAT.
REACH UP.
REACH FOR THE SUN.
FEEL YOUR CHI PATHS CLEARING.
NOW CLOSE YOUR EYES.
HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
I FEEL...
REALLY WARM.
Katara: GOOD, GOOD.
GO ON.
LIKE THERE'S THIS WARM FEELING
ALL AROUND ME.
THIS HEAT.
LIKE I'M IN THE FIRE LORD'S
PALACE AND HE'S SHOOTING
A BUNCH OF FIREBALLS AT ME.
AND THE WHOLE WORLD IS BEING
ENGULFED IN FLAMES.
MAYBE YOUR STRESS IS THE KIND
YOU NEED TO TALK OUT.
[PANTING]
WHY DON'T YOU GET RIGHT DOWN
TO BUSINESS AND TELL ME
WHAT'S BEEN BOTHERING YOU?
YOU KNOW WHAT'S BOTHERING ME.
I HAVE TO FIGHT THE FIRE LORD
IN A FEW DAYS.
MM-HMM... TELL ME MORE
ABOUT THIS... FIRE LORD.
WHY ARE YOU SO AFRAID OF HIM?
YOU SAID IT YOURSELF, HE'S THE
BADDEST MAN ON THE PLANET.
I'M SUPPOSED TO DEFEAT HIM
AND SAVE THE WORLD.
MMM, LIFE DOES FEEL THAT WAY
SOMETIMES, DOESN'T IT?
LIKE WE'RE ALL TRYING TO
SAVE THE WORLD FROM EVIL?
OK, BUT WHAT CAN I DO
TO FEEL BETTER?
WANNA TRY SCREAMING
INTO THIS PILLOW?
[MUFFLED SCREAM]
[BAAS]
Azula: HELLO, ZU-ZU.
IF YOU'VE COME FOR A ROYAL
HAIR-COMBING, I'M AFRAID
YOU'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
SO I GUESS THERE'S A BIG
WAR MEETING COMING UP, HUH?
AND APPARENTLY I'M NOT
WELCOME THERE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
OF COURSE YOU'RE WELCOME THERE.
OH, YEAH?
I GUESS THAT'S WHY NO ONE
BOTHERED TO TELL ME ABOUT IT.
OH, ZUKO, DON'T BE SO DRAMATIC.
I'M CERTAIN DAD WANTS YOU THERE.
YOU PROBABLY JUST
WEREN'T INVITED
BECAUSE IT'S SO OBVIOUS THAT
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE THERE.
WELL, WERE YOU INVITED?
OF COURSE, I'M THE PRINCESS.
AND I'M THE PRINCE.
EXACTLY, SO STOP ACTING LIKE
A PARANOID CHILD.
JUST GO TO THE MEETING.
FORGET IT, I'M NOT GOING.
Toph: ALL RIGHT, WHAT YOU NEED
IS A GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
BACK-POUNDING
TO RELIEVE YOUR STRESS.
POUND AWAY.
AAH, OW...
TOPH, I THINK
THIS IS BRUISING ME.
[GRUNTING]
SORRY, I FORGOT YOU HAVE
BABY SKIN.
WELL, THERE'S ONE OTHER THING
WE CAN TRY.
ACUPUNCTURE.
[SCREAMS]
ZUKO, IT'S JUST A DUMB MEETING.
WHO CARES?
I DON'T.
WELL, GOOD, YOU SHOULDN'T.
I MEAN, WHY WOULD YOU EVEN
WANT TO GO?
JUST THINK ABOUT HOW THINGS WENT
AT THE LAST WAR MEETING
YOU WENT TO.
[SIGHS] I KNOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT WILL MAKE YOU
FEEL BETTER?
ORDERING SOME SERVANTS AROUND.
I MIGHT BE HUNGRY FOR
A WHOLE TRAY OF FRUIT TARTS.
AND MAYBE A LITTLE PALANQUIN
RIDE AROUND TOWN, DOUBLE-TIME.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING, GUYS.
SO DO YOU FEEL LESS STRESSED,
READY FOR A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP?
UH, I KIND OF THINK
I SORT OF MIGHT SLIGHTLY FEEL
A LITTLE BETTER.
MAYBE.
THEN OUR WORK HERE IS DONE.
[YAWNS]
[KATARA AND TOPH YAWN]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[CHATTERING]
[DISTORTED VOICE]
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTS]
[OZAI CACKLING]
[SCREAMS]
SHH...
[ROARS]
WHAT HAPPENED, AANG?
IT'S THE NIGHTMARES.
THEY JUST GET WORSE AND WORSE.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S TIME
FOR ANOTHER THERAPY SESSION.
NO, THAT WON'T HELP.
NOTHING HELPS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING I CAN DO.
I'M GONNA STAY AWAKE STRAIGHT
THROUGH TO THE INVASION.
INVASION...
ALL ABOARD FOR THE INVASION.
YOU DON'T LOOK SO GOOD.
YOU SURE YOU CAN'T JUST LIE DOWN
FOR A LITTLE NAP?
I TOLD YOU, I CAN'T
GO BACK TO SLEEP.
AANG, STAYING UP ALL NIGHT
CAN'T BE GOOD FOR YOU.
ACTUALLY, STAYING UP ALL NIGHT
HAS GIVEN ME SOME TIME TO THINK.
AND I'VE REALIZED
SOME BIG THINGS, KATARA.
WHAT BIG THINGS?
I SEE EVERYTHING
SO CLEARLY NOW.
WHAT REALLY MATTERS,
WHY I'M REALLY DOING THIS.
I'M DOING IT TO SAVE THE WORLD,
BUT MORE THAN THAT...
I'M DOING IT FOR THE PEOPLE
I LOVE.
I'M DOING IT FOR YOU, KATARA.
AANG, WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
I'M SAYING... I LOVE YOU.
WHAT ARE WE DOING?
WHAT OUR HEARTS HAVE BEEN
TELLING US TO DO
FOR A LONG, LONG TIME.
BABY, YOU'RE MY FOREVER GIRL.
Katara: AANG...
UH?
I WAS JUST SAYING
YOU SHOULD TAKE A NAP.
OH, I GUESS I KIND OF
DRIFTED OFF INTO A DAYDREAM.
WHAT WAS YOUR DREAM ABOUT?
UH, LIVING UNDERWATER.
SOUNDS NEAT.
[CHUCKLES]
WHEW.
PRINCE ZUKO, EVERYONE'S
WAITING FOR YOU.
WHAT?
THE HIGH ADMIRALS, HIGH
GENERALS, THE WAR MINISTERS, AND
THE PRINCESS HAVE ALL ARRIVED.
YOU'RE THE ONLY PERSON MISSING.
SO... MY DAD WANTS ME
AT THE MEETING?
THE FIRE LORD SAID HE WOULD NOT
START UNTIL YOU ARRIVED, SIR.
[EXHALES]
PUT 'EM UP, FIRE LORD.
[YELLS]
HEY, I'M TRYING TO BUILD APPA
SOME ARMOR HERE
SO HE DOESN'T HAVE TO GO
INTO THE INVASION NAKED.
HE'S YOUR BISON.
OZAI'S DEFENSE IS IMPECCABLE.
I'LL HAVE TO TRY
A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
[YELLS]
YOU THINK YOU'RE UNTOUCHABLE,
DON'T YOU, MR. FIRE LORD?
Voice: BOY, YOU ARE REALLY
STARTING TO LOSE IT, KID.
MOMO, DID YOU HEAR SOMETHING?
Voice: NO, BUT I SAID SOMETHING.
UH...
YOU, MY FRIEND, ARE JUST A FEW
PLUMS SHORT OF A FRUIT PIE.
[CHATTERING]
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
I'M SO TIRED THAT
FOR A SECOND THERE, I IMAGINED
YOU WERE TALKING TO ME.
[CHATTERS]
OH, MOMO, LET ME EXPLAIN.
[CHATTERING]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
[LAUGHING, CHATTERING]
Katara: AANG?
WE'RE ALL STARTING TO GET
A LITTLE WORRIED ABOUT YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN AWAKE TOO LONG.
AND YOU'RE ACTING
DOWNRIGHT WEIRD.
YOU'VE GOT TO TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF.
YOU CAN'T GO ON LIKE THIS.
[GROANS] LOOK, I APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU GUYS ARE SAYING
BUT THE STRESS
AND THE NIGHTMARES...
THEY WERE JUST TOO MUCH.
STAYING AWAKE IS THE BEST WAY
FOR ME TO DEAL WITH IT.
YEAH, LEAVE THE KID ALONE.
HEY, WHO ASKED YOU?
Aang: GUYS, COME ON.
NO, I AM SICK OF THIS GUY
ALWAYS MOUTHING OFF
AND TELLING ME WHAT TO DO.
OH, YOU DON'T LIKE IT?
WELL, LET'S GO RIGHT NOW.
SOKKA, WHAT SHOULD WE DO?
ABOUT WHAT?
ABOUT THAT.
[ROARING]
[SCREECHING]
[SWORDS CLANG]
APPA, APPA, APPA.
MOMO, MOMO, MOMO.
COME ON, GUYS, WE'RE ALL
ON THE SAME SIDE.
♪ CHAKRAS, CHAKRAS,
EVERYBODY LOVES CHAKRAS ♪
♪ CHAKRAS, CHAKRAS ♪
♪ CHAKRA SANDWICH
TASTES GOOD, YUM... ♪
YAY, YAY, YAY, YAY, YAY!
[WHIMPERS]
[CHEERING]
I JUST NEED TO JUMP IN
A COLD WATERFALL.
[SCREAMING]
SO HOW DID IT GO?
WHEN I GOT TO THE MEETING,
EVERYONE WELCOMED ME.
MY FATHER HAD SAVED ME A SEAT.
HE WANTED ME NEXT TO HIM.
I WAS LITERALLY
AT HIS RIGHT HAND.
ZUKO, THAT'S WONDERFUL.
YOU MUST BE HAPPY.
DURING THE MEETING,
I WAS THE PERFECT PRINCE.
THE SON MY FATHER WANTED.
BUT I WASN'T ME.
OH, LOOK, ANOTHER HALLUCINATION.
AN IMAGINARY BED
MADE OUT OF CLOUDS.
Toph: HEY, IT'S REAL.
WE SPENT HOURS WORKING ON IT.
WE MADE IT FOR YOU.
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP WILL
PROBABLY TAKE THE CRAZY AWAY.
WE HOPE.
LOOK, YOU GUYS KEEP TELLING ME
I NEED TO SLEEP, BUT I CAN'T.
THE INVASION'S TOMORROW.
AANG...
NO, KATARA, THERE'S STILL
SO MUCH I HAVEN'T LEARNED.
I DON'T NEED SLEEP,
WHAT I NEED IS PRACTICE.
QUICK, HIT ME.
I'M NOT GOING TO HIT YOU.
YOU WANT ME TO DO IT?
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'VE BEEN TRAINING FOR THIS
SINCE THE DAY WE MET.
I'VE SEEN YOUR PROGRESS.
YOU'RE SMART, BRAVE,
AND STRONG ENOUGH.
YOU REALLY THINK SO?
WE ALL DO.
YOU CAN DO THIS,
YOU'RE READY.
YOU'RE THE MAN, TWINKLE TOES.
THANKS, GUYS.
[YAWNS]
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK I AM READY.
YOUR DAYS OF TYRANNY
ARE OVER, FIRE LORD.
REALLY, YOU'RE GOING TO
TAKE ME OUT?
YOU'RE NOT EVEN WEARING PANTS.
NO, FIRE LORD OZAI,
YOU'RE NOT WEARING PANTS.
[GASPS, SCREAMS]
NO!
MY ROYAL PARTS ARE SHOWING.
[OZAI SCREAMS]
♪