Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS LIVED
TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED
AND MY BROTHER AND I DISCOVERED
THE NEW AVATAR...
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
YOU AND SOKKA HAVE TO GO
WITH AANG SOMEWHERE SAFE.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO KEEP HOPE ALIVE.
I'M GOING TO JOIN THE AVATAR,
AND I'M GOING TO HELP HIM
DEFEAT YOU.
SINCE YOU'RE A FULL-BLOWN
TRAITOR NOW AND YOU WANT ME
GONE, WHY WAIT?
BECAUSE I KNOW MY OWN DESTINY.
TAKING YOU DOWN
IS THE AVATAR'S DESTINY.
Aang: I KNOW JUST THE PLACE
FOR US TO GO WHERE WE'LL BE SAFE
FOR A WHILE.
THE WESTERN AIR TEMPLE.
[APPA SNORTING...]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
THIS IS HUMILIATING.
DO YOU MEAN GETTING THOROUGHLY
SPANKED BY THE FIRE NATION
OR HAVING TO WALK ALL THE WAY
TO THE WESTERN AIR TEMPLE?
BOTH.
SORRY, GUYS, BUT APPA GETS TIRED
CARRYING ALL THESE PEOPLE.
I WONDER HOW THE REST
OF THE TROOPS ARE.
THEY'RE PROBABLY ON THEIR WAY
TO A PRISON.
SEEMS LIKE MY DAD JUST GOT OUT,
NOW HE'S GOING BACK IN.
I MISS PIPSQUEAK.
I MISS NOT HAVING BLISTERS
ON MY FEET.
HEY, WE'RE HERE.
I CAN FEEL IT.
Katara: UH, I THINK YOUR FEET
NEED THEIR EYES CHECKED.
NO, SHE'S RIGHT, WE ARE HERE.
Toph: WOW, IT'S AMAZING.
Iroh: WHAT A STUNNING VIEW.
THE ONLY VIEW I'M INTERESTED IN
SEEING IS THE AVATAR IN CHAINS.
YOU KNOW, THE AVATAR HASN'T BEEN
SEEN FOR 100 YEARS.
THE CHANCES OF FINDING HIM HERE
ARE VERY SLIM.
FIRST, WE'LL CHECK
EACH OF THE AIR TEMPLES.
THEN WE'LL SCOUR THE WORLD,
SEARCHING EVEN THE MOST REMOTE
LOCATIONS UNTIL WE FIND HIM.
PRINCE ZUKO, IT'S ONLY BEEN
A WEEK SINCE YOUR BANISHMENT.
YOU SHOULD TAKE SOME TIME
TO HEAL AND REST.
WHAT ELSE WOULD I EXPECT TO HEAR
FROM THE LAZIEST MAN
IN THE FIRE NATION?
[SIGHS]
THE ONLY WAY TO REGAIN MY HONOR
IS TO FIND THE AVATAR.
SO I WILL.
[GROANS]
[APPA GRUNTING...]
IT'S SO DIFFERENT FROM
THE NORTHERN AIR TEMPLE.
I WONDER IF THERE ARE
ANY SECRET ROOMS.
LET'S GO CHECK IT OUT.
YOU GUYS GO... I THINK WE NEED
TO TALK ABOUT SOME THINGS.
I'LL RACE YOU, DUKE.
I TOLD YOU, IT'S "THE DUKE."
WHY CAN'T I GO?
WE NEED TO DECIDE
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO NOW
AND SINCE YOU'RE THE AVATAR,
MAYBE YOU SHOULD BE
A PART OF THIS.
FAIR ENOUGH.
SO WHAT'S THE NEW PLAN?
WELL, IF YOU ASK ME,
THE NEW PLAN IS THE OLD PLAN.
YOU JUST NEED TO MASTER ALL FOUR
ELEMENTS AND CONFRONT THE FIRE
LORD BEFORE THE COMET COMES.
OH, YEAH, THAT'S GREAT,
NO PROBLEM, I'LL JUST DO THAT.
AANG, NO ONE SAID
IT'S GONNA BE EASY.
WELL, IT'S NOT EVEN GONNA
BE POSSIBLE.
WHERE AM I SUPPOSED TO GET
A FIREBENDING TEACHER?
WE COULD LOOK FOR JEONG JEONG.
YEAH, RIGHT.
LIKE WE'LL EVER RUN INTO
JEONG JEONG AGAIN.
WHO'S... OH, NEVER MIND.
IF IT'S IMPORTANT,
I'LL FIND OUT.
OH, WELL, GUESS WE CAN'T
COME UP WITH ANYBODY.
WHY DON'T WE JUST TAKE A NICE
TOUR AROUND THE TEMPLE?
[MOMO CHATTERING]
Toph: WHAT'S UP WITH HIM?
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOMEONE
WHO CAN TEACH HIM FIREBENDING.
HELLO, ZUKO HERE.
BUT I GUESS YOU PROBABLY ALREADY
KNOW ME... SORT OF.
UH, SO, THE THING IS, I HAVE
A LOT OF FIREBENDING EXPERIENCE
AND I'M CONSIDERED TO BE
PRETTY GOOD AT IT.
WELL, YOU'VE SEEN ME... YOU
KNOW, WHEN I WAS ATTACKING YOU?
UH, YEAH, I GUESS I SHOULD
APOLOGIZE FOR THAT.
BUT ANYWAY, I'M GOOD NOW.
I MEAN, I THOUGHT I WAS GOOD
BEFORE, BUT NOW I REALIZE
I WAS BAD.
BUT ANYWAY... I THINK IT'S TIME
I JOINED YOUR GROUP
AND TAUGHT THE AVATAR
FIREBENDING.
[CROAKING]
WELL, WHAT'S YOUR ANSWER?
[CROAKS]
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT I'D SAY TOO.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO CONVINCE
THESE PEOPLE I'M ON THEIR SIDE?
WHAT WOULD UNCLE DO?
"ZUKO, YOU HAVE TO LOOK
WITHIN YOURSELF
"TO SAVE YOURSELF
FROM YOUR OTHER SELF.
ONLY THEN WILL YOUR TRUE SELF
REVEAL ITSELF."
[SIGHS]
EVEN WHEN I'M TALKING FOR HIM, I
CAN'T FIGURE OUT WHAT HE MEANS.
WHAT WOULD AZULA DO?
"LISTEN, AVATAR,
I CAN JOIN YOUR GROUP
"OR I CAN DO SOMETHING
UNSPEAKABLY HORRIBLE TO YOU
AND YOUR FRIENDS.
YOUR CHOICE."
I GUESS I'M NOT THAT GOOD
AT IMPERSONATIONS.
[CROAKS]
[APPA GROANING...]
Katara: AANG, CAN WE TALK ABOUT
YOU LEARNING FIREBENDING NOW?
WHAT?
THE WIND IS TOO LOUD IN MY EARS.
CHECK OUT THIS LOOP.
[MOMO CHATTERING]
Sokka: AANG, I THINK
WE SHOULD BE MAKING SOME PLANS
ABOUT OUR FUTURE.
Aang: OK, WE CAN DO THAT
WHILE I SHOW YOU
THE GIANT PAI SHO TABLE.
OH, AND YOU'RE GONNA LOVE
THE ALL-DAY ECHO CHAMBER.
I THINK THAT'LL HAVE TO WAIT.
[APPA GROANING]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
HELLO, ZUKO HERE.
HEY, I HEARD YOU GUYS FLYING
AROUND DOWN THERE, SO I JUST
THOUGHT I'D WAIT FOR YOU HERE.
[ROARS]
[GRUNTS]
I KNOW YOU MUST BE SURPRISED
TO SEE ME HERE.
NOT REALLY, SINCE YOU'VE
FOLLOWED US ALL OVER THE WORLD.
RIGHT... WELL, UH...
ANYWAY, WHAT I WANTED TO TELL
YOU ABOUT IS THAT I'VE CHANGED
AND I, UH, I'M GOOD NOW.
AND, WELL, I THINK I SHOULD
JOIN YOUR GROUP.
OH, AND I CAN TEACH
FIREBENDING...
TO YOU.
SEE, I, UH...
YOU WANT TO WHAT NOW?
YOU CAN'T POSSIBLY THINK
THAT ANY OF US WOULD TRUST YOU,
CAN YOU?
I MEAN, HOW STUPID
DO YOU THINK WE ARE?
YEAH, ALL YOU'VE EVER DONE
IS TRY TO HUNT US DOWN
AND CAPTURE AANG.
I'VE DONE SOME GOOD THINGS.
I MEAN, I COULD'VE STOLEN
YOUR BISON IN BA SING SE,
BUT I SET HIM FREE.
THAT'S SOMETHING.
APPA DOES SEEM TO LIKE HIM.
HE PROBABLY JUST COVERED HIMSELF
IN HONEY OR SOMETHING
SO THAT APPA WOULD LICK HIM.
I'M NOT BUYING IT.
I CAN UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU WOULDN'T TRUST ME
AND I KNOW I'VE MADE SOME
MISTAKES IN THE PAST.
Sokka: LIKE WHEN YOU ATTACKED
OUR VILLAGE?
OR WHEN YOU STOLE
MY MOTHER'S NECKLACE AND USED IT
TO TRACK US DOWN AND CAPTURE US?
LOOK, I ADMIT I'VE DONE
SOME AWFUL THINGS.
I WAS WRONG TO TRY TO
CAPTURE YOU, AND I'M SORRY THAT
I ATTACKED THE WATER TRIBE.
AND I NEVER SHOULD'VE SENT THAT
FIRE NATION ASSASSIN AFTER YOU.
I'M GONNA TRY TO STOP HIM.
WAIT, YOU SENT COMBUSTION MAN
AFTER US?
WELL, THAT'S NOT
HIS NAME, BUT...
OH, SORRY, I DIDN'T MEAN TO
INSULT YOUR FRIEND.
HE'S NOT MY FRIEND.
THAT GUY LOCKED ME AND KATARA
IN JAIL AND TRIED TO
BLOW US ALL UP.
WHY AREN'T YOU SAYING ANYTHING?
YOU ONCE SAID YOU THOUGHT
WE COULD BE FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW I HAVE GOOD IN ME.
THERE'S NO WAY WE CAN TRUST YOU
AFTER EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE.
WE'LL NEVER LET YOU JOIN US.
Katara: YOU NEED TO
GET OUT OF HERE, NOW.
I'M TRYING TO EXPLAIN THAT
I'M NOT THAT PERSON ANYMORE.
EITHER YOU LEAVE
OR WE ATTACK.
IF YOU WON'T ACCEPT ME
AS A FRIEND, THEN MAYBE
YOU'LL TAKE ME AS A PRISONER.
NO, WE WON'T.
[GRUNTS]
Katara: GET OUT OF HERE
AND DON'T COME BACK.
AND IF WE EVER SEE YOU AGAIN...
WELL, WE'D BETTER NOT
SEE YOU AGAIN.
[MOMO CHATTERING]
[GROANS] I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW STUPID I AM.
I MEAN, WHAT WAS I THINKING?
TELLING THEM I SENT AN ASSASSIN
AFTER THEM?
WHY DIDN'T I JUST SAY
AZULA DID THAT?
THEY WOULD'VE BELIEVED THAT.
STUPID.
[CROAKS]
[GROANS]
Katara: WHY WOULD HE TRY TO
FOOL US LIKE THAT?
Sokka: OBVIOUSLY, HE WANTS TO
LEAD US INTO SOME KIND OF TRAP.
Katara: THIS IS JUST LIKE
WHEN WE WERE IN PRISON TOGETHER
IN BA SING SE.
HE STARTS TALKING ABOUT
HIS MOTHER
AND MAKING IT SEEM LIKE
HE'S AN ACTUAL HUMAN BEING
WITH FEELINGS.
HE WANTS YOU TO TRUST HIM
AND FEEL SORRY FOR HIM
SO YOU LET YOUR GUARD DOWN,
THEN HE STRIKES.
THE THING IS, IT WORKED.
I DID FEEL SORRY FOR HIM.
I FELT LIKE HE WAS REALLY
CONFUSED AND HURT.
BUT OBVIOUSLY WHEN THE TIME CAME
HE MADE HIS CHOICE
AND WE PAID THE PRICE.
WE CAN'T TRUST HIM.
Aang: I KIND OF HAVE
A CONFESSION TO MAKE.
REMEMBER WHEN YOU TWO WERE SICK
AND I GOT CAPTURED BY ZHAO?
AND YOU MADE US
SUCK ON FROZEN FROGS?
HOW COULD I FORGET?
I HAD A WART ON THE FLAP
THAT HANGS DOWN FROM THE BACK
OF MY THROAT FOR A MONTH.
SOKKA, I LOOKED AT IT AND TOLD
YOU THERE WAS NOTHING THERE.
I COULD FEEL IT...
IT'S MY THROATAL FLAP.
Aang: ANYWAY, WHEN ZHAO
HAD ME CHAINED UP, IT WAS ZUKO
WHO CAME IN AND GOT ME OUT.
HE RISKED HIS LIFE TO SAVE ME.
NO WAY, I'M SURE HE ONLY DID IT
SO HE COULD CAPTURE YOU HIMSELF.
YEAH, FACE IT, AANG, YOU'RE
NOTHING BUT A BIG PRIZE TO HIM.
YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
AND WHAT WAS ALL THAT CRAZY
STUFF ABOUT SETTING APPA FREE?
WHAT A LIAR.
ACTUALLY, HE WASN'T LYING.
OH, HOORAY.
IN A LIFETIME OF EVIL,
AT LEAST HE DIDN'T ADD
ANIMAL CRUELTY TO THE LIST.
I'M JUST SAYING THAT
CONSIDERING HIS MESSED-UP FAMILY
AND HOW HE WAS RAISED
HE COULD'VE TURNED OUT
A LOT WORSE.
YOU'RE RIGHT, TOPH, LET'S GO
FIND HIM AND GIVE HIM A MEDAL...
THE "NOT AS MUCH OF A JERK
AS YOU COULD'VE BEEN" AWARD.
ALL I KNOW IS THAT WHILE HE WAS
TALKING TO US, HE WAS SINCERE.
MAYBE YOU'RE ALL JUST
LETTING YOUR HURT FEELINGS
KEEP YOU FROM THINKING CLEARLY.
EASY FOR YOU TO SAY,
YOU WEREN'T THERE WHEN HE HAD US
ATTACKED BY PIRATES.
OR WHEN HE BURNED DOWN
KYOSHI ISLAND.
OR WHEN HE TRIED TO CAPTURE ME
AT THE FIRE TEMPLE.
WHY WOULD YOU EVEN
TRY TO DEFEND HIM?
BECAUSE, KATARA, YOU'RE ALL
IGNORING ONE CRUCIAL FACT.
AANG NEEDS A
FIREBENDING TEACHER.
WE CAN'T THINK OF
A SINGLE PERSON IN THE WORLD
TO DO THE JOB.
NOW ONE SHOWS UP
ON A SILVER PLATTER AND
YOU WON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT?
I'M NOT HAVING ZUKO
AS MY TEACHER.
YOU'RE DARN RIGHT
YOU'RE NOT, BUDDY.
WELL, I GUESS THAT'S SETTLED.
[GROANS] I'M BEGINNING TO WONDER
WHO'S REALLY THE BLIND ONE
AROUND HERE.
[LEAVES RUSTLING]
WHO'S THERE?
STAY BACK.
IT'S ME!
OW!
YOU BURNED MY FEET.
I'M SORRY, IT WAS A MISTAKE.
GET AWAY FROM ME.
LET ME HELP YOU.
I'M SORRY.
GET OFF ME, GET OFF ME.
[GRUNTS]
I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS YOU.
[GROANS]
COME BACK!
WHY AM I SO BAD AT BEING GOOD?
HAS ANYONE SEEN TOPH?
I HAVEN'T SEEN HER
SINCE SHE STORMED OFF YESTERDAY.
MAYBE SHE'S JUST EXPLORING
THE AIR TEMPLE.
THERE ARE SOME PRETTY FUN SPOTS
TO PRACTICE EARTHBENDING.
I THINK WE SHOULD
GO LOOK FOR HER.
OH, LET HER HAVE FUN
WITH HER ROCKS.
I'M IN NO RUSH TO HAVE HER
YELLING AT US AGAIN.
WE CAN GO CHECK FOR HER.
YEAH, I WANT TO RIDE
THAT TUNNEL DOWN TO
THE HALL OF STATUES AGAIN.
IT'LL WORK A LOT BETTER
NOW THAT I FIXED MY BRAKES.
[CRASH]
[GRUNTING]
Katara: TOPH, WHAT HAPPENED?
MY FEET GOT BURNED.
OH, NO, WHAT HAPPENED?
I JUST TOLD YOU,
MY FEET GOT BURNED.
I MEANT HOW.
WELL, I KIND OF WENT TO SEE ZUKO
LAST NIGHT.
YOU WHAT?
ZUKO?
[GASPS]
I JUST THOUGHT HE COULD BE
HELPFUL TO US
AND IF I TALKED TO HIM, MAYBE
WE COULD WORK SOMETHING OUT.
SO HE ATTACKED YOU?
WELL, HE DID AND HE DIDN'T.
IT WAS SORT OF AN ACCIDENT.
BUT HE DID FIREBEND AT YOU?
[SIGHS] YES.
SEE, YOU TRUSTED ZUKO AND
YOU GOT BURNED... LITERALLY.
IT'S GONNA TAKE A WHILE
FOR YOUR FEET TO GET BETTER.
I WISH I COULD'VE WORKED
ON THEM SOONER.
YEAH, ME TOO.
ZUKO'S CLEARLY TOO DANGEROUS
TO BE LEFT ALONE.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO
GO AFTER HIM.
I HATE TO GO LOOKING FOR
A FIGHT, BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
AFTER WHAT HE DID TO TOPH,
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE A CHOICE.
HE'S CRAFTY, BUT WE'LL FIND
A WAY TO CAPTURE HIM.
Toph: MAYBE JUST INVITE HIM
BACK HERE.
HE'S ALREADY OFFERED HIMSELF UP
AS A PRISONER ONCE.
YEAH... GET HIM TO COME BACK
AND SAY HE'LL BE OUR PRISONER
THEN WE'LL JUMP HIM AND REALLY
MAKE HIM OUR PRISONER.
HE'LL NEVER SUSPECT IT.
YOU ARE A MASTER
OF SURPRISE, SOKKA.
AHH, THAT'S THE STUFF.
NOW I KNOW HOW
THE REST OF YOU GUYS FEEL.
NOT BEING ABLE TO SEE
WITH YOUR FEET STINKS.
[GRUNTS]
Zuko: STOP!
I DON'T WANT YOU
HUNTING THE AVATAR ANYMORE.
THE MISSION IS OFF.
I'M ORDERING YOU TO STOP.
[GRUNTS]
IF YOU KEEP ATTACKING,
I WON'T PAY YOU.
[GRUNTS] ALL RIGHT,
I'LL PAY YOU DOUBLE TO STOP.
[GRUNTS]
[ROARS]
HE'S GOING TO BLAST THIS WHOLE
PLACE RIGHT OFF THE CLIFFSIDE.
[EXPLOSION]
I CAN'T STEP OUT TO WATERBEND
AT HIM WITHOUT GETTING BLOWN UP.
AND I CAN'T GET A GOOD ENOUGH
ANGLE ON HIM FROM DOWN HERE.
I KNOW HOW TO GET
AN ANGLE ON HIM.
ALL RIGHT, BUDDY,
DON'T FAIL ME NOW.
[GRUNTS]
YEAH, BOOMERANG!
AW, BOOMERANG...
[GRUNTS]
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M SAYING THIS,
BUT THANKS, ZUKO.
HEY, AND WHAT ABOUT ME?
I DID THE BOOMERANG THING.
LISTEN, I KNOW I DIDN'T EXPLAIN
MYSELF VERY WELL YESTERDAY.
I'VE BEEN THROUGH A LOT
IN THE PAST FEW YEARS,
AND IT'S BEEN HARD.
BUT I'M REALIZING THAT I HAD TO
GO THROUGH ALL THOSE THINGS
TO LEARN THE TRUTH.
I THOUGHT I HAD LOST MY HONOR
AND THAT SOMEHOW MY FATHER
COULD RETURN IT TO ME.
BUT I KNOW NOW THAT NO ONE CAN
GIVE YOU YOUR HONOR.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU EARN
FOR YOURSELF BY CHOOSING
TO DO WHAT'S RIGHT.
ALL I WANT NOW IS TO PLAY
MY PART IN ENDING THIS WAR.
AND I KNOW MY DESTINY IS
TO HELP YOU RESTORE BALANCE
TO THE WORLD.
I'M SORRY FOR WHAT I DID TO YOU.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
FIRE CAN BE DANGEROUS AND WILD.
SO AS A FIREBENDER,
I NEED TO BE MORE CAREFUL
AND CONTROL MY BENDING
SO I DON'T HURT PEOPLE
UNINTENTIONALLY.
I THINK YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO BE
MY FIREBENDING TEACHER.
WHEN I FIRST TRIED TO LEARN
FIREBENDING, I BURNED KATARA.
AND AFTER THAT, I NEVER WANTED
TO FIREBEND AGAIN.
BUT NOW I KNOW YOU UNDERSTAND
HOW EASY IT IS TO HURT
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
I'D LIKE YOU TO TEACH ME.
THANK YOU.
I'M SO HAPPY YOU'VE ACCEPTED ME
INTO YOUR GROUP.
Aang: NOT SO FAST.
I STILL HAVE TO ASK MY FRIENDS
IF IT'S OK WITH THEM.
TOPH, YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT ZUKO BURNED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GO AHEAD AND LET HIM JOIN.
IT'LL GIVE ME PLENTY OF TIME
TO GET BACK AT HIM
FOR BURNING MY FEET.
SOKKA?
HEY, ALL I WANT IS TO DEFEAT
THE FIRE LORD.
IF YOU THINK THIS IS THE WAY
TO DO IT, THEN I'M ALL FOR IT.
KATARA?
I'LL GO ALONG WITH
WHATEVER YOU THINK IS RIGHT.
I WON'T LET YOU DOWN, I PROMISE.
SO HERE YOU GO, HOME SWEET HOME.
I GUESS, YOU KNOW, FOR NOW.
UNPACK... LUNCH SOON.
UH... WELCOME ABOARD?
YEAH.
OK, THIS IS REALLY,
REALLY WEIRD.
IF I HAVE TO, I WILL SPEND
EVERY DAY OF THE REST OF MY LIFE
HUNTING THE AVATAR.
I KNOW IT'S MY DESTINY
TO CAPTURE HIM.
YOU KNOW, PRINCE ZUKO,
DESTINY IS A FUNNY THING.
YOU NEVER KNOW HOW THINGS
ARE GOING TO WORK OUT
BUT IF YOU KEEP AN OPEN MIND
AND AN OPEN HEART
I PROMISE YOU WILL FIND
YOUR OWN DESTINY SOMEDAY.
Katara: YOU MIGHT HAVE
EVERYONE ELSE HERE BUYING
YOUR TRANSFORMATION.
BUT YOU AND I BOTH KNOW
YOU'VE STRUGGLED WITH DOING
THE RIGHT THING IN THE PAST.
SO LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING
RIGHT NOW.
YOU MAKE ONE STEP BACKWARD,
ONE SLIP-UP, GIVE ME ONE REASON
TO THINK YOU MIGHT HURT AANG
AND YOU WON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT YOUR DESTINY ANYMORE
BECAUSE I'LL MAKE SURE
YOUR DESTINY ENDS
RIGHT THEN AND THERE...
PERMANENTLY.
♪