Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS LIVED
TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED
AND MY BROTHER AND I DISCOVERED
THE NEW AVATAR...
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Aang: SO WHAT'S THE NEW PLAN?
Sokka: THE NEW PLAN
IS THE OLD PLAN.
YOU JUST NEED TO MASTER
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS
AND CONFRONT THE FIRE LORD
BEFORE THE COMET COMES.
WHERE AM I SUPPOSED TO GET
A FIREBENDING TEACHER?
HELLO.
ZUKO HERE.
I THINK IT'S TIME
I JOINED YOUR GROUP AND TAUGHT
THE AVATAR FIREBENDING
AND I KNOW MY DESTINY
IS TO HELP YOU RESTORE
BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
I THINK YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO BE
MY FIREBENDING TEACHER.
[MEN VOCALIZING RHYTHMICALLY]
Zuko: I KNOW YOU'RE NERVOUS,
BUT REMEMBER, FIREBENDING
IN AND OF ITSELF
IS NOT SOMETHING TO FEAR.
[SIGHING]
OK.
NOT SOMETHING TO FEAR.
BUT IF YOU DON'T RESPECT IT
IT'LL CHEW YOU UP
AND SPIT YOU OUT
LIKE AN ANGRY KOMODO RHINO.
[GASPING]
NOW, SHOW ME WHAT YOU'VE GOT.
ANY AMOUNT OF FIRE YOU CAN MAKE.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
MAYBE I NEED
A LITTLE MORE INSTRUCTION.
PERHAPS A DEMONSTRATION?
Zuko: GOOD IDEA.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE
A COUPLE STEPS BACK.
[INHALES]
[GRUNTING]
WHAT WAS THAT?
THAT WAS THE WORST FIREBENDING
I'VE EVER SEEN.
I THOUGHT IT WAS NICE.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
WHY IS THIS HAPPENING?
MAYBE IT'S THE ALTITUDE.
YEAH, COULD BE.
[GRUNTING...]
[YAWNING]
JUST BREATHE, AND...
THAT ONE KIND OF FELT HOT.
DON'T PATRONIZE ME.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S
SUPPOSED TO LOOK LIKE.
SORRY, SIFU HOTMAN.
AND STOP CALLING ME THAT.
Sokka: HEY, JERKS.
MIND IF I WATCH YOU TWO JERKS
DO YOUR JERK BENDING?
GET OUT OF HERE.
OK, TAKE IT EASY.
I WAS JUST KIDDING AROUND.
[CHUCKLING]
JERK BENDING.
STILL GOT IT.
[GROANING]
[GROWLING]
Zuko: LISTEN, EVERYBODY.
I'VE GOT SOME PRETTY BAD NEWS.
I'VE LOST MY STUFF.
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
I DIDN'T TOUCH YOUR STUFF.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
MY FIREBENDING.
IT'S GONE.
[KATARA LAUGHING]
I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST LAUGHING AT THE IRONY.
YOU KNOW, HOW IT WOULD'VE
BEEN NICE FOR US
IF YOU'D LOST YOUR FIREBENDING
A LONG TIME AGO?
WELL, IT'S NOT LOST.
IT'S JUST WEAKER
FOR SOME REASON.
MAYBE YOU'RE JUST NOT AS GOOD
AS YOU THINK YOU ARE.
OUCH.
[GROWLING]
I BET IT'S BECAUSE
I CHANGED SIDES.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE IT ISN'T.
MAYBE YOUR FIREBENDING
COMES FROM RAGE
AND YOU JUST DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH ANGER TO FUEL IT
THE WAY YOU USED TO.
SO ALL WE NEED TO DO
IS MAKE ZUKO ANGRY.
EASY ENOUGH.
[LAUGHING]
OK, CUT IT OUT!
LOOK.
EVEN IF YOU'RE RIGHT,
I DON'T WANT TO RELY
ON HATE AND ANGER ANYMORE.
THERE HAS TO BE ANOTHER WAY.
YOU'RE GONNA NEED TO LEARN
TO DRAW YOUR FIREBENDING
FROM A DIFFERENT SOURCE.
I RECOMMEND THE ORIGINAL SOURCE.
HOW'S HE SUPPOSED TO DO THAT?
BY JUMPING INTO A VOLCANO?
NO.
ZUKO NEEDS TO GO BACK
TO WHATEVER THE ORIGINAL
SOURCE OF FIREBENDING IS.
SO IS IT JUMPING INTO A VOLCANO?
I DON'T KNOW.
FOR EARTHBENDING, THE ORIGINAL
BENDERS WERE BADGERMOLES.
ONE DAY, WHEN I WAS LITTLE,
I RAN AWAY AND HID IN A CAVE.
[CRYING]
[CRASHING]
THAT'S WHERE I MET THEM.
[GROWLING]
[LAUGHING]
THEY WERE BLIND, JUST LIKE ME,
SO WE UNDERSTOOD EACH OTHER.
I WAS ABLE
TO LEARN EARTHBENDING,
NOT JUST AS A MARTIAL ART
BUT AS AN EXTENSION
OF MY SENSES.
FOR THEM,
THE ORIGINAL EARTHBENDERS,
IT WASN'T JUST ABOUT FIGHTING.
IT WAS THEIR WAY
OF INTERACTING WITH THE WORLD.
Aang: THAT'S AMAZING, TOPH.
I LEARNED FROM THE MONKS,
BUT THE ORIGINAL AIRBENDERS
WERE THE SKY BISON.
MAYBE YOU CAN GIVE ME
A LESSON SOMETIME, BUDDY.
[GROWLING]
WELL, THIS DOESN'T HELP ME.
THE ORIGINAL FIREBENDERS
WERE THE DRAGONS,
AND THEY'RE EXTINCT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
ROKU HAD A DRAGON,
AND THERE WERE PLENTY OF DRAGONS
WHEN I WAS A KID.
WELL, THEY AREN'T
AROUND ANYMORE, OK?
OK, OK.
SORRY.
Zuko: BUT MAYBE
THERE'S ANOTHER WAY.
THE FIRST PEOPLE
TO LEARN FROM THE DRAGONS
WERE THE ANCIENT SUN WARRIORS.
Aang: SUN WARRIORS?
WELL, I KNOW THEY WEREN'T AROUND
WHEN I WAS A KID.
NO, THEY DIED OFF
THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO
BUT THEIR CIVILIZATION WASN'T
TOO FAR FROM WHERE WE ARE NOW.
MAYBE WE CAN LEARN SOMETHING
BY POKING AROUND THE RUINS.
IT'S LIKE THE MONKS
USED TO TELL ME.
SOMETIMES, THE SHADOWS
OF THE PAST CAN BE FELT
BY THE PRESENT.
Sokka: SO WHAT?
MAYBE YOU'LL PICK UP SOME
SUPER OLD SUN WARRIOR ENERGY
JUST BY STANDING WHERE
THEY STOOD 1,000 YEARS AGO?
Zuko: MORE OR LESS.
EITHER I FIND A NEW WAY
TO FIREBEND, OR THE AVATAR
HAS TO FIND A NEW TEACHER.
[WHOOSHING]
WE'VE BEEN RIDING FOR HOURS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY,
BUT I THOUGHT THIS THING
WOULD BE A LOT FASTER.
[GROWLING]
APPA'S RIGHT, ZUKO.
IN OUR GROUP, TYPICALLY,
WE START OUT OUR MISSIONS
WITH A MORE UPBEAT ATTITUDE.
[GROANING]
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'LL GET THE HANG OF IT.
WHOA!
Zuko: EVEN THOUGH
THESE BUILDINGS ARE ANCIENT
THERE'S SOMETHING EERILY
FAMILIAR ABOUT THEM.
I CAN TELL THE FIRE SAGES'
TEMPLES ARE SOMEHOW
DESCENDED FROM THESE.
OK, WE'VE LEARNED SOMETHING
ABOUT ARCHITECTURE.
HOPEFULLY, WE'LL LEARN SOMETHING
ABOUT FIREBENDING TOO.
THE PAST CAN BE A GREAT TEACHER.
[SCREAMING]
[AANG GRUNTING]
[WHIMPERING]
ZUKO, I THINK THE PAST
IS TRYING TO KILL ME.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THIS BOOBY TRAP MUST
BE CENTURIES OLD,
AND IT STILL WORKS.
THERE'S PROBABLY A LOT MORE.
MAYBE THIS MEANS
WE SHOULDN'T BE HERE.
WHERE'S THAT UPBEAT ATTITUDE
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT?
BESIDES, PEOPLE DON'T MAKE TRAPS
UNLESS THEY'VE GOT
SOMETHING WORTH PROTECTING.
LOOK.
THIS SEEMS PROMISING.
THOUGH I'M NOT SURE WHAT
THIS TELLS US ABOUT THE ORIGINAL
SOURCE OF FIREBENDING.
THEY LOOK PRETTY ANGRY TO ME.
Aang: I THOUGHT THE DRAGONS WERE
FRIENDS WITH THE SUN WARRIORS.
Zuko: WELL, THEY HAD
A FUNNY WAY OF SHOWING IT.
ZUKO, SOMETHING HAPPENED
TO THE DRAGONS IN
THE LAST 100 YEARS.
SOMETHING YOU'RE NOT TELLING ME.
MY GREAT-GRANDFATHER
SOZIN HAPPENED.
HE STARTED THE TRADITION
OF HUNTING DRAGONS FOR GLORY.
THEY WERE
THE ULTIMATE FIREBENDERS
AND IF YOU COULD CONQUER ONE,
YOUR FIREBENDING TALENTS
WOULD BECOME LEGENDARY
AND YOU'D EARN
THE HONORARY TITLE, DRAGON.
THE LAST GREAT DRAGON
WAS CONQUERED LONG BEFORE
I WAS BORN, BY MY UNCLE.
BUT I THOUGHT YOUR UNCLE WAS,
I DON'T KNOW, GOOD?
HE HAD A COMPLICATED PAST.
FAMILY TRADITION, I GUESS.
LET'S JUST MOVE ON.
[GRUNTING]
IT'S LOCKED UP.
WAIT.
IT'S A CELESTIAL CALENDAR.
JUST LIKE THE FIRE SAGES
HAVE IN THEIR TEMPLES.
I BET THAT SUN STONE
OPENS THE DOOR
BUT ONLY WHEN SUNLIGHT HITS IT
AT JUST THE RIGHT ANGLE,
ON THE SOLSTICE.
MONKEY FEATHERS.
THE SOLSTICE AGAIN.
WE CAN'T WAIT HERE THAT LONG.
NO, WE CAN'T.
BUT WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SPEED TIME UP.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN OUTSMART
THE SUN STONE.
NOTHING'S HAPPENING.
COME ON.
[RUMBLING]
YOU KNOW, ZUKO, I DON'T CARE
WHAT EVERYONE ELSE
SAYS ABOUT YOU.
YOU'RE PRETTY SMART.
[GASPING]
RELAX.
THEY'RE JUST STATUES.
IT SAYS THIS IS SOMETHING
CALLED THE DANCING DRAGON.
ZUKO, GET OVER HERE.
I WANT YOU TO DANCE WITH ME.
WHAT?
JUST DO IT.
[ZUKO GROANING]
LET'S FOLLOW THE STEPS
OF THE STATUES.
DON'T YOU SEE?
THESE AREN'T DANCE MOVES.
THESE STATUES ARE GIVING US
A LESSON.
I THINK THIS IS SOME KIND
OF SUN WARRIOR FIREBENDING FORM.
THIS BETTER TEACH US
SOME REALLY GOOD FIREBENDING.
HOORAY!
WAIT.
WHAT EXACTLY IS THAT?
IT'S SOME KIND
OF MYSTICAL GEMSTONE.
WELL, DON'T TOUCH IT.
WHY NOT?
REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED OUT THERE
WITH THOSE SPIKES?
I'M JUST VERY SUSPICIOUS
OF GIANT, GLOWING GEMS
SITTING ON PEDESTALS.
IT FEELS ALMOST ALIVE.
[SCREAMING]
OH, NO, IT'S ANOTHER TRAP.
[GROANING]
I CAN'T PULL FREE.
IT'S LIKE SOME KIND OF GLUE.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
I CAN'T MOVE.
ZUKO, DO SOMETHING.
ME?
I CAN'T MOVE EITHER.
[GROANING]
IT STOPPED.
AT LEAST WE HAVE AIR.
MAYBE IF WE STAY CALM,
WE CAN FIGURE A WAY OUT OF THIS.
YOU HAD TO PICK UP
THE GLOWING EGG, DIDN'T YOU?
AT LEAST I MADE
SOMETHING HAPPEN.
IF IT WERE UP TO YOU, WE'D NEVER
HAVE MADE IT PAST THE COURTYARD.
HELP!
WHO ARE YOU YELLING TO?
NOBODY'S LIVED HERE
FOR CENTURIES.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK
WE SHOULD DO?
THINK ABOUT OUR PLACE
IN THE UNIVERSE?
[SIGHING]
WHO IS DOWN THERE?
FOR TRYING TO TAKE
OUR SUN STONE, YOU MUST
BE SEVERELY PUNISHED.
WE DIDN'T COME HERE
TO TAKE YOUR SUN STONE.
WE CAME HERE TO FIND
THE ANCIENT ORIGIN
OF ALL FIREBENDING.
Man: YEAH, RIGHT.
THEY ARE OBVIOUSLY THIEVES,
HERE TO STEAL
SUN WARRIOR TREASURES.
Aang: PLEASE.
I DON'T NORMALLY PLAY THIS CARD,
BUT I'M THE AVATAR.
JUST HEAR US OUT.
MY NAME IS ZUKO,
CROWN PRINCE OF THE FIRE NATION.
OR AT LEAST, I USED TO BE.
I KNOW MY PEOPLE HAVE DISTORTED
THE WAYS OF FIREBENDING,
TO BE FUELLED BY ANGER AND RAGE
BUT NOW I WANT TO LEARN
THE TRUE WAY, THE ORIGINAL WAY.
WHEN WE CAME HERE, I NEVER
IMAGINED THE SUN WARRIOR
CIVILIZATION WAS SECRETLY ALIVE.
I AM TRULY HUMBLED
TO BE IN YOUR PRESENCE.
PLEASE, TEACH US.
IF YOU WISH TO LEARN
THE WAYS OF THE SUN
YOU MUST LEARN THEM FROM
THE MASTERS RAN AND SHAO.
RAN AND SHAO?
THERE ARE TWO OF THEM?
WHEN YOU PRESENT YOURSELVES
TO THEM, THEY WILL EXAMINE YOU.
THEY'LL READ YOUR HEARTS,
YOUR SOULS, AND YOUR ANCESTRY.
IF THEY DEEM YOU WORTHY,
THEY'LL TEACH YOU.
IF THEY DON'T, YOU'LL BE
DESTROYED ON THE SPOT.
Chief: IF YOU'RE GOING TO SEE
THE MASTERS, YOU MUST BRING THEM
A PIECE OF THE ETERNAL FLAME.
THIS FIRE IS THE VERY FIRST ONE.
IT WAS GIVEN TO MAN
BY THE DRAGONS.
WE HAVE KEPT IT GOING
FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
Chief: YOU WILL EACH TAKE
A PIECE OF IT TO THE MASTERS
TO SHOW YOUR COMMITMENT TO
THE SACRED ART OF FIREBENDING.
UM, MISTER SUN CHIEF, SIR?
YEAH, I'M NOT A FIREBENDER YET.
COULDN'T MY FRIEND HERE
CARRY MY FIRE FOR ME?
NO.
THIS RITUAL ILLUSTRATES
THE ESSENCE OF
SUN WARRIOR PHILOSOPHY.
YOU MUST MAINTAIN
A CONSTANT HEAT.
THE FLAME WILL GO OUT
IF YOU MAKE IT TOO SMALL.
MAKE IT TOO BIG,
AND YOU MIGHT LOSE CONTROL.
I'M SORRY.
I'M JUST A LITTLE NERVOUS.
IT'S LIKE A LITTLE HEARTBEAT.
FIRE IS LIFE,
NOT JUST DESTRUCTION.
YOU WILL TAKE
YOUR FLAMES UP THERE.
THE CAVE OF THE MASTERS
IS BENEATH THAT ROCK.
HURRY UP.
I CAN'T.
IF I WALK TOO FAST,
MY FLAME'LL GO OUT.
YOUR FLAME'S GONNA GO OUT
BECAUSE IT'S TOO SMALL.
YOU'RE TOO TIMID.
GIVE IT MORE JUICE.
BUT WHAT IF I CAN'T CONTROL IT?
YOU CAN DO IT.
I KNOW YOU CAN.
YOU'RE A TALENTED KID.
FACING THE JUDGMENT
OF THE FIREBENDING MASTERS
WILL BE VERY DANGEROUS FOR YOU.
YOUR ANCESTORS
ARE DIRECTLY RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE DRAGONS' DISAPPEARANCE.
THE MASTERS MIGHT NOT BE
SO HAPPY TO SEE YOU.
I KNOW I WOULDN'T BE.
BUT ONCE THEY FIND OUT
I'M THE AVATAR...
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
THAT YOU VANISHED
ALLOWING THE FIRE NATION
TO WREAK HAVOC ON THE WORLD?
THE DECLINE OF THE DRAGONS
IS YOUR BURDEN TOO.
WE COULD TURN BACK NOW.
WE'VE ALREADY LEARNED MORE
ABOUT FIRE THAN WE'D HOPED.
NO, WE'RE SEEING THIS
THROUGH TO THE END.
WE'RE GONNA MEET THESE MASTERS
AND FIND OUT WHAT'S
SO GREAT ABOUT THEM.
WHAT IF THEY JUDGE US
AND ATTACK US?
WELL, WE'RE THE FIRE PRINCE
AND THE AVATAR.
I THINK WE COULD TAKE THESE GUYS
IN A FIGHT, WHOEVER THEY ARE.
BRING 'EM OUT.
CHANTERS!
[MEN VOCALIZING RHYTHMICALLY...]
THOSE WHO WISH TO MEET
THE MASTERS RAN AND SHAO
WILL NOW PRESENT THEIR FIRE.
SOUND THE CALL.
[HORN BLOWING]
[CRASHING]
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
[GASPING]
ZUKO, MY FIRE WENT OUT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
GIVE ME SOME OF YOURS.
[GRUNTING]
NO, JUST MAKE YOUR OWN.
I CAN'T.
[GRUNTING]
Zuko: GET SOME FROM ONE
OF THOSE WARRIORS.
HURRY.
STOP CHEATING OFF ME.
Aang: QUIT BEING STINGY.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[CRASHING]
Both: UH-OH.
[DRAGON GROWLING]
THESE ARE THE MASTERS.
YOU STILL THINK WE CAN TAKE 'EM?
SHH.
I NEVER SAID THAT.
OH, HERE IT COMES.
ANY MOMENT NOW.
DINNER FOR THE MASTERS.
QUIET, HAM GHAO.
WHAT?
EVERYONE'S THINKING IT.
ZUKO, I THINK WE'RE SUPPOSED TO
DO THE DRAGON DANCE WITH THEM.
WHAT?
WHAT ABOUT THIS SITUATION
MAKES YOU THINK
THEY WANT US TO DANCE?
WELL, I THINK THEY
WANT US TO DO SOMETHING.
LET'S JUST TRY IT.
FINE.
JUDGMENT TIME.
[DRAGON GROWLING]
[WHIMPERING]
[AANG AND ZUKO SCREAMING]
[GASPING]
I UNDERSTAND.
THEIR FIRE WAS BEAUTIFUL.
I SAW SO MANY COLORS,
COLORS I'VE NEVER IMAGINED.
Aang: LIKE FIREBENDING HARMONY.
YES.
THEY JUDGED YOU,
AND GAVE YOU VISIONS OF
THE MEANING OF FIREBENDING.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THERE
ARE STILL LIVING DRAGONS.
MY UNCLE IROH SAID HE FACED
THE LAST DRAGON AND KILLED IT.
SO YOUR UNCLE LIED.
ACTUALLY, IT WASN'T A TOTAL LIE.
IROH WAS THE LAST OUTSIDER
TO FACE THE MASTERS.
THEY DEEMED HIM WORTHY
AND PASSED THE SECRET
ON TO HIM AS WELL.
Zuko: HE MUST'VE LIED
TO PROTECT THEM, SO NO ONE
ELSE WOULD HUNT THEM.
ALL THIS TIME, I THOUGHT
FIREBENDING WAS DESTRUCTION.
SINCE I HURT KATARA, I'VE BEEN
TOO AFRAID AND HESITANT
BUT NOW I KNOW
WHAT IT REALLY IS.
IT'S ENERGY, AND LIFE.
YEAH.
IT'S LIKE THE SUN,
BUT INSIDE OF YOU.
DO YOU GUYS REALIZE THIS?
WELL, OUR CIVILIZATION IS CALLED
THE SUN WARRIORS, SO YEAH.
THAT'S WHY MY FIREBENDING
WAS SO WEAK BEFORE
BECAUSE FOR SO MANY YEARS,
HUNTING YOU WAS MY DRIVE.
IT WAS MY PURPOSE.
SO WHEN I JOINED YOU,
I LOST SIGHT OF MY INNER FIRE.
BUT NOW, I HAVE A NEW DRIVE.
I HAVE TO HELP YOU
DEFEAT MY FATHER AND RESTORE
BALANCE TO THE WORLD.
NOW THAT YOU HAVE LEARNED
THE SECRETS AND YOU KNOW
ABOUT OUR TRIBE'S EXISTENCE
WE HAVE NO CHOICE BUT
TO IMPRISON YOU HERE FOREVER.
JUST KIDDING.
BUT SERIOUSLY,
DON'T TELL ANYONE.
Aang: WITH THIS TECHNIQUE
THE DRAGONS SHOWED US,
ZUKO AND I WILL BE UNSTOPPABLE.
[APPLAUSE]
Sokka: YEAH, THAT'S A GREAT
DANCE YOU TWO LEARNED THERE.
IT'S NOT A DANCE.
IT'S A FIREBENDING FORM.
WE'LL JUST TAP DANCE OUR WAY
TO VICTORY OVER THE FIRE LORD.
IT'S A SACRED FORM THAT HAPPENS
TO BE THOUSANDS OF YEARS OLD.
OH, YEAH?
WHAT'S YOUR LITTLE FORM CALLED?
THE DANCING DRAGON.
[LAUGHTER]
[MEN VOCALIZING RHYTHMICALLY...]
♪