- KATARA: Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I discovered
the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
- Ugh!
- KATARA: But I believe
Aang can save the world.
- ♪
- Sokka's your name, right?
My favorite prisoner used
to mention you all the time.
She was convinced you were
going to come rescue her.
Of course, you never came,
and she gave up on you.
- Where is Suki?
How are we all gonna escape?
- We're not.
You kids have to leave.
You have to escape
on Appa together.
- Goodbye, Dad.
We won't be apart for
too long this time.
I promise.
- [calm music]
♪
- ZUKO: No one can
make tea like Uncle.
But hopefully I learned
a thing or two.
Would you like to hear
Uncle's favorite tea joke?
- KATARA: Sure.
- AANG: I like jokes.
- TOPH: Bring it!
- Okay, well, I can't
remember how it starts,
but the punchline is
"Leaf me alone-- I'm bushed!"
- [crickets chirping]
- Well, it's funnier
when Uncle tells it.
- Right.
Maybe that's because he
remembers the whole thing.
- [laughter]
- It's nice to get a
chance to relax a little.
It hardly ever happens.
- Hey, can I talk
to you for a second?
- So what's up?
- SOKKA: If someone was
captured by the Fire Nation,
where would they be taken?
- ZUKO: What do you mean?
Who was captured?
- When the invasion plan failed,
some of our troops were taken.
I just want to know
where they might be.
- I can't tell you.
- What?
Why not?
- Trust me.
Knowing will just
make you feel worse.
- It's my dad.
He was captured too.
I need to know what
I put him through.
- It's not good, Sokka.
- Please.
- My guess is they were
taken to the Boiling Rock.
- What's that?
- ZUKO: The highest-security
prison in the Fire Nation.
It's on an island in the
middle of the boiling lake.
It's inescapable.
- So where is this place?
- Why do you need to know?
What are you planning?
- Nothing.
Boy, you're so paranoid.
- It's in the middle
of a volcano
between here
and the Fire Nation.
You guys actually flew right
past it on the way here.
- Thanks, Zuko.
[yawns]
Just knowing
makes me feel better.
- Yeah, I'm sure it does.
- [snores]
- ♪
- [sighs]
Huh?
- [snores]
- [water rushing]
- Shh!
- Not up to anything, huh?
- Aah!
- [thud]
- [groans]
Fine, you caught me.
I'm gonna rescue my dad.
You happy now?
- I'm never happy.
- Look, I have to do this.
The invasion plan was my idea.
It was my decision to stay
when things were going wrong.
It's my mistake,
and it's my job to fix it.
I have to regain my honor.
You can't stop me, Zuko.
- You need to regain your honor?
Believe me, I get it.
I'm going with you.
- No!
I have to do this alone.
- How are you
going to get there?
On Appa?
Last time I checked, prisons
don't have bison daycares.
- [sighs]
- We'll take my war balloon.
- [snores]
- [birds chirping]
- [growls]
- What does it say?
- "Need meat.
Gone fishing.
"Back in a few days.
Sokka and Zuko."
- [yawns]
- "One more thing.
"Aang, practice your
firebending while I'm gone.
"Do 20 sets of fire fists
and 10 hop squats
"every time you hear
a badger frog croak.
"Zuko."
- [badger frog croaking]
- [sighs]
Nobody else has homework.
One hop squat, two hop squat,
three hop squat, four hop squat.
- [fire rumbling]
- [whirring]
- Pretty clouds.
- Yeah, fluffy.
- SOKKA: [whistles]
- What?
Oh, I didn't say anything.
You know, a friend of mine
actually designed
these war balloons.
- No kidding.
- Yup.
A balloon, but for war.
- If there's one thing my
dad's good at, it's war.
- Yeah, it seems to
run in the family.
- Hey, hold on.
Not everyone in my
family is like that.
- I know, I know.
You've changed.
- I meant my uncle.
He was more of a father to me.
And I really let him down.
- I think your uncle
would be proud of you.
Leaving your home
to come help us?
That's hard.
- It wasn't that hard.
- Really?
You didn't leave behind
anyone you cared about?
- Well, I did have
a girlfriend, Mai.
- That gloomy girl
who sighs a lot?
- Yeah.
Everyone in the Fire Nation
thinks I'm a traitor.
I couldn't drag her into it.
- My first girlfriend
turned into the moon.
- That's rough, buddy.
- [snores]
- [fire rumbling]
- [whirring]
- There it is.
- Huh? Huh?
- There's plenty of
steam to keep us covered.
As long as we're quiet,
we should be able to navigate
through it without being caught.
- [adventurous music]
♪
- We're going down.
The balloon's not
working anymore.
- SOKKA: The air outside is
just as hot as the air inside,
so we can't fly.
- Whoa!
So what are we supposed to do?
- I don't know.
Crash landing?
- [splashing]
- [yelps]
- [groaning]
- [sputters]
- ZUKIO: How are we gonna
get off the island
if the balloon won't work?
- We'll figure something out.
I suspected it might
be a one-way ticket.
- You knew this would happen
and you wanted to come anyway?
- My dad might be here.
I had to come and see.
- Uncle always said I never
thought things through.
But this?
This is just crazy!
- Hey, I never wanted you to
come along in the first place.
And for the record,
I always think things through.
But my plans
haven't exactly worked.
So this time,
I'm playing it by ear.
So there!
- [sizzling]
- Aah!
- ZUKO: What are you doing?
- It doesn't work anyway, and
we don't want anyone to find it.
- I hope you know
what you're doing.
There's no turning back now.
- [creaking]
- I hope these disguises work.
- We just need to lay low and
find my dad as soon as possible.
- Guards!
There's a scuffle in the yard.
Come on!
- ♪
- I didn't do anything.
I'm going back to my cell.
- Stop right there, Chit Sang!
- We can't blow our cover.
- I've had it with
your unruly behavior.
- What did I do?
- He wants to know what he did.
Isn't that cute?
- Uh, very cute, sir.
- Super cute.
- You didn't bow down when
I walked by, Chit Sang.
- What?
That's not a prison rule.
- Do it!
- Make me.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [fire rumbling]
- [clucks tongue]
Firebending is prohibited.
You're goin' in the cooler.
- You!
Help me take him in.
- Meet back here in an hour.
- ♪
- The warden will
deal with you soon.
- [groans]
- Can you believe this guy?
- Prisoners!
Am I right?
- [growls]
Tell me about it.
- [indistinct chatter]
- Ha ha!
Hey, new guy!
I know it's the rule to have
your helmet on at all times,
but this is the lounge.
Relax!
- But what if
there's an incident?
If I'm not prepared, someone
could strike me on the head.
- [laughter]
- Give it a week.
He'll loosen up.
- Can the new guy
ask you veterans
a few questions
about the prison?
- No, you can't date
the female guards.
- Trust me, you don't want to.
- [smack]
- [laughs]
- No, that's not it.
The Boiling Rock.
It holds the Fire Nation's
most dangerous criminals, right?
So what about war prisoners?
- [ominous music]
♪
- [whoosh]
- [pants]
- It sure looks cold in there.
- That's why we
call it the cooler.
He won't be
firebending in there.
- [footsteps]
- It's the warden!
Look alive!
- ♪
- So, Chit Sang, I hear you used
firebending to try to escape.
You should know better.
- I wasn't trying to escape.
- MALE GUARD: He's lying!
I saw him with my own eyes.
- No one has ever,
ever escaped from here.
I'd sooner jump in
the boiling lake myself
than let that record fall.
Don't forget it.
Now go back to your shivering.
- [door shuts]
- [indistinct chatter]
- Hey, there, fellow guard.
How goes it?
- Zuko?
- Shh!
Listen, I asked
around the lounge.
There are no
Water Tribe prisoners.
I'm afraid your
father's not here.
- What?
Are you sure?
Did you double check?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- No. No!
- I'm really sorry, Sokka.
- So we came all
this way for nothing?
I failed... again.
- Ah, what would Uncle say?
Sometimes clouds have two
sides, a dark and light,
and a silver lining in between.
It's like a silver sandwich.
So when life seems hard, take a
bite out of the silver sandwich.
- Maybe we haven't
failed after all!
- That's the spirit!
I can't believe that worked.
I didn't even know
what I was saying.
- No, what you said
made no sense at all.
But look!
It's Suki!
- MALE GUARD: Prisoners!
Back in your cells!
- [bell ringing]
- [whirring]
- [mopping sounds]
- [door opens and shuts]
- What is it?
Did I do something wrong?
- You mean you
don't recognize me?
- You people all
look the same to me.
- Oh?
Then maybe you'll
recognize this.
- [harps]
- [smooching sounds]
[groans]
- Sokka!
It's you!
- The other Kyoshi Warriors,
are they here?
- No.
I don't know where they are.
They locked me in here
because I'm the leader.
- Well, you won't
be here for long.
I'm busting you out.
- I'm so glad to see you, Sokka.
I knew you'd come.
- [footsteps]
- [clanging]
- Excuse me.
I need to get into that cell.
- No, you can't go in there.
The lights are out.
The prisoner could
sneak up on you.
- Step aside, fool!
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
- SOKKA: [groans]
- [clanging]
- [groaning]
- Guard, help!
I think he's an imposter!
Aah!
Arrest him!
- Get him off me and arrest him!
- [groaning]
- You're under arrest!
Don't worry, I'll figure it out.
- [boiling]
- [door opens]
- Well, well, well.
I never thought I'd find
you in here, Prince Zuko.
- How did you know who I am?
- How could I not?
You broke my niece's heart.
- You're Mai's uncle?
I never meant to hurt her.
- Quiet!
You're my special prisoner now.
And you best behave.
If these criminals
found out who you are--
the traitor prince who
let his nation down--
why, they'd tear you to shreds.
- So what's in it for you?
Why don't you just tell my
father and collect a reward?
- Oh, in due time, believe me.
I intend to collect.
- [footsteps]
- Oh, good.
You guys have met.
- Actually, we met
a long time ago.
- We did?
- Yeah, you kinda
burned down my village.
- Oh, sorry about that.
Nice to see you again.
- So listen, I think
I have an escape plan.
I checked out the coolers again.
The whole point of them
is to keep
Firebenders contained, right?
- Yeah.
- So they're completely
insulated and sealed
to keep the cold in.
Well, to keep the cold in,
it also has to keep
the heat out, right?
- Just get to the point, Sokka.
- It's a perfect boat
for getting through
the boiling water.
- The cooler as a boat?
Are you sure?
- I'm telling you, it'll work.
I walked around the perimeter.
There's a blind spot
between two guard towers.
It's the perfect
launching point.
I already tested it out.
We'll roll the cooler
into the water
and just float with the current.
It'll take us straight across.
As long as we don't make a
sound, no one will notice.
And bing, bang, boom,
we're home free!
- But how are you gonna
get the cooler out?
- Yeah, how are you
gonna get the cooler out?
- What?
We didn't-- we didn't say that!
- Yeah, you heard wrong.
- I heard you hatching an
escape plan, and I want in.
- There's nothing to get in on.
- Yeah, the only thing
we're hatching is... an egg?
- [sighing]
- Okay, well, I come with you,
or the warden hears
about this egg too.
- I guess we have no choice.
- Okay, you're in.
Now, first we need someone
to unbolt the cooler
from the inside.
- Oh, I can get you inside.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [groans]
Hey, what are you?
Stupid?
Watch where you're going!
- [groaning]
- Hey, you watch
who you're shoving!
- I think you mean
whom I'm shoving.
- [grunting]
- [cheering]
- [groaning]
- I need backup over here!
- [grunts]
- [fire rumbling]
- No firebending.
Into the cooler!
- [groans]
- [tense music]
♪
- [gusting]
- I can take you
back to your cell
if you've learned your lesson.
- [fire rumbling]
- Yes, I have-- completely.
- I got Suki and Chit Sang
out of their cells
a few minutes ago.
They'll be waiting
for us at the shore.
- [footsteps]
- Someone's coming!
- Yeah, new arrivals
coming in at dawn.
- Anybody interesting?
- Nah, just the usual.
Some robbers, couple of
traitors, some war prisoners.
Though I did hear there
might be a pirate.
- FEMALE GUARD: No foolin'!
- War prisoners.
It could be your father.
- I know.
- Well, what should we do?
Are we going ahead with the plan
or are we waiting another night?
- I don't know.
Is it right for me to
risk Suki's freedom,
all of our freedom,
on the slim chance
that my dad is gonna show up?
- It's your call, Sokka.
- [boiling]
- ♪
- Took you guys long enough.
This here's my girl
and my best buddy.
They're coming too.
- Fine.
Everybody in the cooler.
Let's go.
- ♪
Are you sure you wanna go?
You're the one who said you
wanted to redeem yourself,
redeem your honor.
Rescuing your dad
is your chance.
- Your dad?
- If I had just cut my
losses at the invasion,
maybe we wouldn't
be in this mess.
Maybe sometimes
it's just better
to call it quits
before you fail.
- No, it's not.
Look, Sokka,
you're going to fail a lot
before things work out.
- That's supposed to
make me feel better?
- Even though
you'll probably fail
over and over and over again--
- Seriously, not helping.
- --you have to try every time.
You can't quit because
you're afraid you might fail.
- Hey, if you two are done
cuddling, can we get a move on?
- No, I'm staying.
You guys go.
You've been here long enough.
- I'm not leaving
without you, Sokka.
- I'm staying too.
- Not me.
I'm out.
Let's roll, baby.
- [splash]
- We gave up our only
chance of escaping.
I hope we haven't just
made a huge mistake.
- [boiling]
- Ah, this current is so slow.
I can use this to paddle.
[grunts]
- [sizzling]
- [screams]
- [bell clanging]
- Guards, secure the perimeter
and lock down the prisoners!
Now!
- [fire rumbling]
- The plan failed!
They're caught!
- Get the fugitives and
throw them in the cooler!
- Uh, they are in a cooler, sir.
- One that's bolted down and
not floating in the water!
This is a lockdown!
We have new prisoners arriving.
Everything must be
completely secure.
- [clanking]
- [splash]
- [tense music]
♪
- The gondola's moving.
- [whirring]
- ♪
- This is it.
- [clank]
- If my dad's not there, we
risked everything for nothing.
- We had to.
- Come on, come on!
- [clank]
- ZUKO: Is that him?
- My dad doesn't
have a nose ring.
Where is he?
That's it?
That can't be it.
- I'm sorry, Sokka.
- Oh no!
- MALE GUARD: Hey, you!
Get off the gondola!
- ♪
- Dad.
- [boiling]
- Line 'em up for the warden!
- ♪
- Dad.
Excuse me, coming through!
The warden wants me
over there, sorry!
- Welcome to the Boiling Rock.
I'm sure you've all heard
the horrible rumors
about our little island.
Well, I just want to tell you
that they don't have to be true,
as long as you do
everything I say.
Look me in the eye when
I'm talking to you.
- No.
- Oh, you'd rather
look at my shoes?
Then take a look!
- Aah!
- I know exactly who you are,
Hakoda of the Water Tribe.
So strong-willed.
But don't worry.
We'll get rid of that in time.
Now look me in the eye!
- [water boiling]
- See, isn't that better?
You will all do as I
say or pay the price.
You will always--
[grunts]
[sputters]
- Are you okay, sir?
- I'm fine!
Get these prisoners
out of my sight.
- ♪
- [door opens]
- Thank goodness you're okay!
- If you take one step closer,
you'll see just how okay I am.
- Dad, it's me.
- Sokka?
My son.
[chuckles]
You know, Sokka,
you should be more careful
with that guard outfit on.
I almost punched you in the gut.
- Yeah, I ran into
that problem earlier.
- [footsteps]
- [clank]
- Are you comfortable,
Chit Sang?
- If you're trying to get
me to talk, forget it!
I'm not a squealer.
- Chit Sang, I only ask you
if you were comfortable.
- Well, yeah, actually,
I am pretty comfortable.
[grunts]
- WARDEN: Are you
still comfortable?
- No.
- WARDEN: I know you and your
cronies are not smart enough
to come up with
that little escape plan.
So you're gonna tell me who is.
- [tense music]
♪
- So where's Bato?
Where's everyone else
from the invasion?
- The others are being held
at a prison
near the Fire Nation palace.
They singled me out as their
leader and sent me here.
But before I left,
I met some young women
who said they knew you.
The Oshinama Fighters?
- You mean the Kyoshi Warriors?
- That's right.
- Their leader, Suki, is here,
and she's gonna escape with us.
- Good, we'll need all
the help we can get.
- And you know Prince Zuko?
- The son of the Fire Lord?
I don't know him,
but I know of him.
- Well, he's here too.
- Sounds like a major problem.
- Actually, he's
on our side now.
I know, I had the same reaction.
After all he's done, it
was hard to trust him.
But he's really proven himself,
and I never would've found you
without his help.
- So, do you have a plan?
- We had one,
but some of the other prisoners
got involved and ruined it.
I don't know if there's
another way off this island.
- Sokka, there's no prison
in the world
that can hold
two Water Tribe geniuses.
- Then we better find two.
- [laughs]
- [chuckles nervously]
- [tense music]
♪
- Zuko, are you there?
- I'm here.
- I just got done
talking to my dad.
We came up with an
escape plan together.
- MALE GUARD: What
are you doing here?
- I was just telling this dirty
lowlife what I think of him!
- Well, you'll have
to do that later.
He's coming with us.
- Why?
- Because we have orders
straight from the warden,
that's why.
- Can I just get 10 more
seconds to rough him up a bit?
- Fine, 10 seconds.
- [opens and shuts door]
- SOKKA: Take that!
And this!
- Newbie!
- ZUKO: [grunts]
- We have a new plan, but it's
gonna need a big distraction.
Be in the yard in one hour.
- [door opens]
- [groaning]
- All right, that's enough.
- ZUKO: What are you doing?
Where are you taking me?
Aah!
I didn't do anything wrong.
- Come on, Zuko.
We all know that's a lie.
- Mai.
- [footsteps]
- How is he?
- I think he's ready to talk.
- [groans]
[pants]
- Have you had enough time
to think about what I asked?
- Yes.
- And?
- You're right.
There was another person
involved in the escape plan.
- Who?
- It's a guy who's disguised
like a prison guard,
only he's not a prison guard.
He's the mastermind.
He came up with the plan.
- How did you know I was here?
- Because I know you so well.
- But how--
- The warden's my
uncle, you idiot.
- [groans]
- The truth is, I
guess I don't know you.
All I get is a letter?
You could've at least
looked me in the eye
when you ripped out my heart.
- I didn't mean to--
- You didn't mean to?
"Dear Mai, I'm sorry that you
have to find out this way,
"but I'm leaving."
- Stop!
This isn't about you!
This is about the Fire Nation.
- Thanks, Zuko.
That makes me feel all better.
- Mai, I never
wanted to hurt you.
But I have to do this
to save my country.
- Save it?
You're betraying your country.
- That's not how I see it.
- [whooshing]
- Sokka, what's going on?
- I don't have much time.
If I'm seen with you, the guards
might think something's up.
I just talked to my dad.
- That's great.
- Yeah, and we're escaping
today... on the gondola.
- What?
- My dad and I came up
with the plan together.
We're gonna commandeer
the gondola
and we're gonna take
a hostage with us
so they won't cut the lines.
- We'll never make
it on to the gondola.
There's too many guards.
- My dad already
thought of that.
He said we'll need
a distraction.
That's why we're gonna
start a prison riot.
- Okay, let's say by some
miracle this all works
and we make it on the gondola.
The warden will still
just cut the lines
even if we have a captive.
- Not if the warden
is the captive.
- [clanking]
- [footsteps]
- I have to go.
I'll find you before
we start the riot.
- Hey, you!
The warden wants to see you!
- Why?
- I don't know.
I didn't ask.
- Maybe I could schedule
another time with him?
How's tomorrow?
- He wants to see you now.
- WARDEN: Put him in the lineup.
- [whimpers]
- WARDEN: One of you
is an imposter
who thought he could fool me.
But now that person is going
to be in a lot of trouble.
Who is it?
- [teeth chattering]
- CHIT SANG: That's him, Warden.
He's the imposter!
- What?
I am not!
He's lying!
He's a liar!
- [footsteps]
- [exhales]
- I'm telling you, it wasn't me.
- Save your breath.
I know you've been
working together.
You threw Chit Sang in the very
cooler they used to escape.
It was all part of your plan.
- That was just a coincidence!
- [door opens]
- Sir, there's
someone to see you.
- Who told you to interrupt me?
- I did.
- WARDEN: Princess Azula!
Uh, it is an honor
to welcome you
to the Fire Nation's
most exemplary prison.
I didn't realize
you were coming.
- Who is this?
- He's a guard
who was involved in a recent
and feeble escape attempt.
- It wasn't me!
- Quiet, you!
- You're wasting your time.
That's not one of them.
- How do you know?
- Because I'm a people person.
- [clank]
- [footsteps]
- Hey, I just got orders.
Let the prisoners
out into the yard.
- But we're in the
middle of lockdown.
- Oh, okay.
I'll just go tell the
warden you said that.
I'm sure he'll be glad
to hear about you
undermining his authority.
What's your name again?
- Wait, uh, don't
tell the warden.
I'm just a little confused.
- Hey, I'm confused too.
But the warden's in a
bad mood and irrational.
So if you ask me,
it's best not to question it
and just do what he says.
- Yeah, you're right.
We're letting them out!
- [bell ringing]
- [indistinct chatter]
- This is it.
We have to start a riot.
- Okay, but how do we do that?
- [indistinct chatter]
- I'll show you.
- [grunts]
Hey!
What did you do that for?
That hurt my feelings.
- Aren't you mad at me?
- Uh, well,
normally I would be,
but I've been learning
to control my anger.
- [squeaking]
- This isn't working.
- Hey, you!
You're lucky I
didn't rat you out.
But my generosity
comes with a price.
I know you're planning another
escape attempt, and I want in.
- Actually, we're trying
to escape right now,
but we need a riot.
You wouldn't happen to know
how to start one, would you?
- A prison riot?
Please.
- [gasps]
- Hey!
Riot!
- PRISONERS: [shouting]
- Impressive.
- Forget about
controlling my anger.
Let's riot!
Whoa!
- [grunts]
- [shooting]
- [grunting]
- WARDEN: Who let these
prisoners into the yard?
This is supposed
to be a lockdown!
- [squeak]
- [twinkling]
- Ma'am, there's
a riot going on.
I'm here to protect you.
- I don't need any protection.
- Heh, believe me, she doesn't.
- I'm sorry, but I'm under
direct orders from your uncle
to make sure nothing happens.
- [fire rumbling]
- Get off of me!
- [shouting]
- [shooting]
- Zuko, good.
We're all here.
Now, all we need to do
is grab the warden
and get to the gondolas.
- And how do we do that?
- I'm not sure.
- Ugh, I thought you'd
thought this through!
- I thought you told me
it's okay not to think
everything through!
- Maybe not everything, but
this is kind of important.
- CHIT SANG: Hey, uh, fellas?
I think your girlfriend's
taking care of it.
- PRISONERS: [shouting]
- [shooting]
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [grunts]
- ♪
- You wouldn't dare.
[grunts]
- Sorry, Warden.
You're my prisoner now.
- [grunts]
- We've got the warden.
Now let's get out of here.
- [panting]
- That's some girl.
- Tell me about it.
- We're almost there.
- [grunts]
- [fire rumbling]
- Back off!
We've go the warden.
- [grunts]
- Let's go.
- [tense music]
♪
- Everyone in.
- ♪
- [clicking]
- [creaking]
- [whirring]
- [grunts]
- [shooting]
- [groans]
What are you doing?
- I'm making it so
they can't stop us.
- Way to think ahead.
- We're on our way.
- Wait, who's that?
- ZUKO: That's a problem.
It's my sister and her friend.
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [whoosh]
- ♪
- This is a rematch
I've been waiting for.
- Me too.
- ♪
- [whooshing]
- [grunting]
- [grunts]
- ♪
- [whooshing]
- WARDEN: [grunts]
- MALE GUARD:
There's the warden.
I see him!
- WARDEN: [grunts]
Cut the line!
- He wants us to cut the line.
- But if we cut the line,
there's no way he'll survive.
- He knows that.
- [creaking]
- [blasts]
- ♪
- [creaking]
- [groans]
[pants]
- They're about to cut the line!
- ♪
- [whirring]
- Then it's time to leave.
- [blast]
- Goodbye, Zuko.
- [eerie music]
♪
- They're cutting the line!
The gondola's about to go!
- CHIT SANG: I hope
this thing floats.
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [grunting]
- What are you doing?
- Saving the jerk who dumped me.
- [fire rumbling]
- [groaning]
- Whoa!
- [grunting]
- [creaking]
- Who is that?
- It's Mai.
- What is she doing?
- ["I don't know" sound]
- [adventurous music]
♪
- [grunts]
- Sorry, Warden.
Your record is
officially broken.
- [grunts]
- [panting]
- Well, we made it out.
Now what?
- Zuko, what are you doing?
- My sister was on that island.
- Yeah, and she's probably right
behind us, so let's not stop.
- What I mean is she
must've come here somehow.
There!
That's our way out of here.
- ♪
- AZUKA: Leave us alone.
I never expected this from you.
The thing I don't
understand is why.
Why would you do it?
You know the consequences.
- I guess you just
don't know people
as well as you think you do.
You miscalculated.
I love Zuko more
than I fear you.
- No, you miscalculated!
You should've feared me more!
- [grunts]
- [gasps]
- Come on!
Let's get outta here!
- You're both fools!
- What shall we do
with them, Princess?
- AZUKA: Put them somewhere
I'll never have to see their
faces again, and let them rot!
- [crickets chirping]
- What are you
doing in this thing?
What happened to
the war balloon?
- It kinda got destroyed.
- Sounds like a
crazy fishing trip.
- Did you at least
get some good meat?
- I did, the best meat of all--
the meat of friendship
and fatherhood.
- I'm new.
What's up, everybody?
- Dad.
- Hi, Katara.
- How are you here?
What is going on?
Where did you go?
- We kind of went to
a Fire Nation prison.
- ♪
- TOPH: Seriously, you
guys didn't find any meat?
- ♪
- MALE:
[vocalizing drumbeats]
♪