Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED
AND MY BROTHER AND I DISCOVERED
THE NEW AVATAR...
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHAT THIS WAR
HAS PUT ME THROUGH.
ME PERSONALLY.
THE FIRE NATION TOOK MY MOTHER
AWAY FROM ME.
I'M SORRY.
- YOU MIGHT HAVE EVERYONE ELSE
HERE BUYING YOUR TRANSFORMATION
BUT YOU AND I BOTH KNOW
YOU'VE STRUGGLED WITH DOING
THE RIGHT THING IN THE PAST.
SO LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING
RIGHT NOW.
YOU MAKE ONE STEP BACKWARD,
ONE SLIP-UP, GIVE ME ONE REASON
TO THINK YOU MIGHT HURT AANG
AND YOU WON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT YOUR DESTINY ANYMORE.
♪
[BIRDS CHIRPING...]
[SNORING]
[YAWNS]
[APPA GRUNTS]
[APPA GROWLS]
Zuko: WATCH OUT!
[GRUNTING]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
KEEPING ROCKS FROM CRUSHING YOU.
OK, I'M NOT CRUSHED,
YOU CAN GET OFF ME NOW.
I'LL TAKE THAT AS A THANK-YOU.
COME ON, WE CAN GET OUT
THROUGH HERE.
[MOMO CHATTERING]
[GROANS] WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GO AHEAD, I'LL HOLD THEM OFF.
I THINK THIS IS A FAMILY VISIT.
ZUKO, NO!
COME ON, WE'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU MEAN IT'S NOT OBVIOUS YET?
I AM ABOUT TO CELEBRATE
BECOMING AN ONLY CHILD.
[SHOUTS]
[APPA GROANS]
Aang: I CAN'T GET HIM
TO GO IN THERE.
APPA HATES TUNNELS.
AANG, THERE'S NO WAY
WE CAN FLY OUT OF HERE.
Aang: WE'LL HAVE TO FIND A WAY.
WE NEED TO SPLIT UP.
TAKE THE TUNNEL AND
GET TO THE STOLEN AIRSHIP.
NO.
THE FIRE NATION CAN'T
SEPARATE OUR FAMILY AGAIN.
IT'LL BE OK.
IT'S NOT FOREVER.
I CAN CLEAR THAT AWAY AND
WE CAN FLY OUT THROUGH THERE.
UM, THERE'S AN AWFUL LOT OF FIRE
IN THAT GENERAL DIRECTION.
WE'LL GET THROUGH.
LET'S GO.
[APPA GROWLING]
[MOMO CHATTERING]
[APPA GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[APPA GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
[APPA GROANS]
SHE'S NOT GONNA MAKE IT.
OF COURSE SHE DID.
[APPA GROANS]
Aang: WOW, CAMPING...
IT REALLY SEEMS LIKE
OLD TIMES AGAIN, DOESN'T IT?
IF YOU REALLY WANT IT TO FEEL
LIKE OLD TIMES, I COULD, UH...
CHASE YOU AROUND AWHILE
AND TRY TO CAPTURE YOU.
[LAUGHTER]
HA-HA.
[SIGHS] TO ZUKO.
WHO KNEW AFTER ALL THOSE TIMES
HE TRIED TO SNUFF US OUT
TODAY HE'D BE OUR HERO.
All: HEAR HEAR.
I'M TOUCHED.
I DON'T DESERVE THIS.
YEAH, NO KIDDING.
WHAT'S WITH HER?
I WISH I KNEW.
Sokka: WHAT'S WITH HIM?
THIS ISN'T FAIR.
EVERYONE ELSE
SEEMS TO TRUST ME NOW.
WHAT IS IT WITH YOU?
OH, EVERYONE TRUSTS YOU NOW?
I WAS THE FIRST PERSON
TO TRUST YOU, REMEMBER?
BACK IN BA SING SE.
AND YOU TURNED AROUND AND
BETRAYED ME, BETRAYED ALL OF US.
WHAT CAN I DO
TO MAKE IT UP TO YOU?
YOU REALLY WANT TO KNOW?
HMM, MAYBE YOU COULD
RECONQUER BA SING SE
IN THE NAME OF THE EARTH KING.
OR, I KNOW, YOU COULD
BRING MY MOTHER BACK.
OOPS.
WRONG TENT.
SORRY, DO YOU NEED TO
TALK TO SOKKA TOO?
NOPE, NOT ME.
WELL, HELLO.
UH, ZUKO, YES, WHY WOULD I BE
EXPECTING ANYONE DIFFERENT?
[GULPS, COUGHS]
SO WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
YOUR SISTER, SHE HATES ME,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY.
BUT I DO CARE
WHAT SHE THINKS OF ME.
NAH, SHE DOESN'T HATE YOU.
KATARA DOESN'T HATE ANYONE.
EXCEPT MAYBE SOME PEOPLE
IN THE FIRE NATION.
NO, I MEAN, UH, NOT PEOPLE
WHO ARE GOOD BUT USED TO BE BAD.
I MEAN BAD PEOPLE.
FIRE NATION PEOPLE WHO ARE STILL
BAD, WHO'VE NEVER BEEN GOOD
AND PROBABLY WON'T BE EVER.
STOP.
OK, LISTEN...
I KNOW THIS MAY SEEM
OUT OF NOWHERE
BUT I WANT YOU TO TELL ME
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR MOTHER.
WHAT?
WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO KNOW THAT?
KATARA MENTIONED IT BEFORE
WHEN WE WERE IN PRISON TOGETHER
IN BA SING SE
AND AGAIN JUST NOW
WHEN SHE WAS YELLING AT ME.
I THINK SOMEHOW...
SHE'S CONNECTED HER ANGER
ABOUT THAT TO HER ANGER AT ME.
IT'S NOT A DAY
I LIKE TO REMEMBER.
[LAUGHING]
I'M GOING TO FIND MOM.
Sokka: MANY OF THE WARRIORS HAD
SEEN THE BLACK SNOW BEFORE
AND THEY KNEW WHAT IT MEANT...
A FIRE NATION RAID.
[SCREAMING]
Sokka: WE WERE BADLY
OUTNUMBERED, BUT SOMEHOW
WE MANAGED TO DRIVE THEM OFF.
AS QUICKLY AS THEY CAME,
THEY JUST LEFT.
I WAS SO RELIEVED
WHEN IT WAS OVER
BUT THAT'S BECAUSE I DIDN'T
KNOW YET WHAT HAD HAPPENED.
I DIDN'T KNOW
WE'D LOST OUR MOTHER.
WAIT, CAN YOU REMEMBER
ANY DETAILS ABOUT THE SOLDIERS
WHO RAIDED YOUR VILLAGE?
LIKE WHAT THE LEAD SHIP
LOOKED LIKE?
YEAH... SEA RAVENS.
THE MAIN SHIP HAD FLAGS
WITH SEA RAVENS ON THEM.
THE SYMBOL OF
THE SOUTHERN RAIDERS.
THANKS, SOKKA.
NO PROBLEM.
THANKS FOR STOPPING BY.
[SIGHS] THOUGHT
HE'D NEVER LEAVE.
SUKI?
[WHISTLING]
YOU LOOK TERRIBLE.
I WAITED OUT HERE ALL NIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I KNOW WHO KILLED YOUR MOTHER.
I'M GOING TO HELP YOU FIND HIM.
I NEED TO BORROW APPA.
WHY, IS IT YOUR TURN TO TAKE
A LITTLE FIELD TRIP WITH ZUKO?
YES, IT IS.
OH... WHAT'S GOING ON?
WE'RE GOING TO FIND THE MAN
WHO TOOK MY MOTHER FROM ME.
Zuko: SOKKA TOLD ME
THE STORY OF WHAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW WHO DID IT,
AND I KNOW HOW TO FIND HIM.
UM, AND WHAT EXACTLY DO YOU
THINK THIS WILL ACCOMPLISH?
[SCOFFS] I KNEW
YOU WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
WAIT, STOP, I DO UNDERSTAND.
YOU'RE FEELING UNBELIEVABLE
PAIN AND RAGE.
HOW DO YOU THINK I FELT
ABOUT THE SANDBENDERS
WHEN THEY STOLE APPA?
HOW DO YOU THINK I FELT ABOUT
THE FIRE NATION WHEN I FOUND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY PEOPLE?
Zuko: SHE NEEDS THIS, AANG.
THIS IS ABOUT GETTING CLOSURE
AND JUSTICE.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK IT'S ABOUT
GETTING REVENGE.
Katara: FINE, MAYBE IT IS.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT I NEED.
MAYBE THAT'S WHAT HE DESERVES.
KATARA, YOU SOUND LIKE JET.
IT'S NOT THE SAME.
JET ATTACKED THE INNOCENT.
THIS MAN, HE'S A MONSTER.
KATARA, SHE WAS MY MOTHER TOO.
BUT I THINK AANG MIGHT BE RIGHT.
THEN YOU DIDN'T LOVE HER
THE WAY I DID.
KATARA...
THE MONKS USED TO SAY
THAT REVENGE IS LIKE
A TWO-HEADED RAT VIPER.
WHILE YOU WATCH YOUR ENEMY
GO DOWN, YOU'RE BEING
POISONED YOURSELF.
THAT'S CUTE, BUT THIS ISN'T
AIR TEMPLE PRESCHOOL.
IT'S THE REAL WORLD.
NOW THAT I KNOW
HE'S OUT THERE...
WE CAN FIND HIM...
I FEEL LIKE I HAVE NO CHOICE.
KATARA, YOU DO HAVE A CHOICE.
FORGIVENESS.
THAT'S THE SAME AS
DOING NOTHING.
NO, IT'S NOT.
IT'S EASY TO DO NOTHING,
BUT IT'S HARD TO FORGIVE.
IT'S NOT JUST HARD,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
SO YOU WERE JUST GONNA
TAKE APPA ANYWAY?
YES.
IT'S OK, BECAUSE I FORGIVE YOU.
THAT GIVE YOU ANY IDEAS?
DON'T TRY TO STOP US.
I WASN'T PLANNING TO.
THIS IS A JOURNEY
YOU NEED TO TAKE.
YOU NEED TO FACE THIS MAN.
BUT WHEN YOU DO,
PLEASE DON'T CHOOSE REVENGE.
LET YOUR ANGER OUT,
AND THEN LET IT GO.
FORGIVE HIM.
OK, WE'LL BE SURE TO DO THAT,
GURU GOODY-GOODY.
- THANKS FOR UNDERSTANDING,
AANG.
YIP-YIP.
[APPA GROANING]
- YOU KNOW, YOU'RE PRETTY WISE
FOR A KID.
- THANKS, SOKKA.
USUALLY IT'S ANNOYING, BUT
RIGHT NOW I'M JUST IMPRESSED.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
SO CAN I BORROW MOMO FOR A WEEK?
WHY DO YOU NEED MOMO?
[HUMS]: I DON'T KNOW.
Zuko: WE NEED TO FIND THE
FIRE NAVY COMMUNICATION TOWER.
ALL THE NAVY'S MOVEMENTS ARE
COORDINATED BY MESSENGER HAWK
AND EVERY TOWER
HAS TO BE UP TO DATE
ON WHERE EVERYONE IS DEPLOYED.
Katara: SO ONCE WE FIND
THE COMMUNICATION TOWER
WE BUST IN AND TAKE
THE INFORMATION WE NEED.
Zuko: NOT EXACTLY.
WE NEED TO BE STEALTHY
AND MAKE SURE NO ONE SPOTS US.
OTHERWISE, THEY'LL WARN
THE SOUTHERN RAIDERS
LONG BEFORE WE REACH THEM.
[DOOR CREAKS]
OK, SOUTHERN RAIDERS.
BAM, ON PATROL
NEAR WHALE TAIL ISLAND.
WHALE TAIL ISLAND,
HERE WE COME.
[APPA GROANS]
YOU SHOULD GET SOME REST.
WE'LL BE THERE IN A FEW HOURS.
YOU'LL NEED ALL YOUR STRENGTH.
OH, DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT MY STRENGTH.
I HAVE PLENTY.
I'M NOT THE HELPLESS LITTLE GIRL
I WAS WHEN THEY CAME.
I'M GOING TO FIND MOM.
MOM!
Mother: JUST LET HER GO...
AND I'LL GIVE YOU
THE INFORMATION YOU WANT.
YOU HEARD YOUR MOTHER...
GET OUT OF HERE!
MOM, I'M SCARED.
GO FIND YOUR DAD, SWEETIE.
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
Katara: I RAN
AS FAST AS I COULD.
DAD, DAD!
PLEASE, I THINK MOM'S
IN TROUBLE!
THERE'S A MAN IN OUR HOUSE.
KYA!
Katara: BUT WE WERE TOO LATE.
WHEN WE GOT THERE,
THE MAN WAS GONE...
AND SO WAS SHE.
YOUR MOTHER WAS A BRAVE WOMAN.
I KNOW.
THERE, SEE THOSE
SEA RAVEN FLAGS?
Zuko: IT'S THE SOUTHERN RAIDERS.
LET'S DO THIS.
SO THERE I WAS, AND I WAS LIKE,
YOU KNOW, IT WAS...
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[APPA SNORTS]
[SCREAMS]
[MAN GRUNTS]
THIS IS IT, KATARA.
ARE YOU READY TO FACE HIM?
[ROARS]
WHO ARE YOU?
YOU DON'T REMEMBER HER?
YOU WILL SOON, TRUST ME.
WHAT'S...
[GRUNTING]
HAPPENING TO ME?
[GROANS]
THINK BACK.
THINK BACK TO YOUR LAST RAID
ON THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
PLEASE, I DON'T KNOW.
DON'T LIE!
YOU LOOK HER IN THE EYE
AND YOU TELL ME YOU DON'T
REMEMBER WHAT YOU DID.
IT'S NOT HIM.
[GRUNTS]
HE'S NOT THE MAN.
WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN HE'S NOT?
HE'S THE LEADER OF
THE SOUTHERN RAIDERS.
HE HAS TO BE THE GUY.
[GRUNTING]
IF YOU'RE NOT THE MAN
WE'RE LOOKING FOR, WHO IS?
YOU MUST BE LOOKING FOR YON RHA.
HE RETIRED FOUR YEARS AGO.
YON RHA, YOU LAZY PIECE OF WORK,
I NEED SOMETHING.
YES, MOTHER.
WHAT IS IT?
THE TOMATO-CARROT FROM YOUR
GARDEN ARE TOO HARD FOR MY GUMS.
I NEED SOMETHING SOFT AND JUICY.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOMETHING ELSE
FROM THE GARDEN?
I WOULD BE HAPPY TO...
FORGET YOUR STUPID GARDEN!
GET YOUR GRIMY HEINIE
TO THE MARKET AND BUY ME
SOME REAL FOOD.
[THUNDER RUMBLING FAINTLY]
[WIND CHIMES RINGING...]
HELLO?
DID YOU SEE SOMEONE?
IS SOMEONE THERE?
THAT WAS HIM.
THAT WAS THE MONSTER.
[THUNDER RUMBLING...]
NOBODY SNEAKS UP ON ME
WITHOUT GETTING BURNED.
[GRUNTS]
WE WEREN'T BEHIND THE BUSH.
AND I WOULDN'T TRY
FIREBENDING AGAIN.
WHOEVER YOU ARE, TAKE MY MONEY,
TAKE WHATEVER YOU WANT.
I'LL COOPERATE.
DO YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
NO... I'M NOT SURE.
OH, YOU BETTER REMEMBER ME
LIKE YOUR LIFE DEPENDS ON IT.
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
A CLOSER LOOK?
YES, YES, I REMEMBER YOU NOW.
YOU'RE THE LITTLE
WATER TRIBE GIRL.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
JUST LET HER GO AND I'LL GIVE
YOU THE INFORMATION YOU WANT.
YOU HEARD YOUR MOTHER.
GET OUT OF HERE.
MOM, I'M SCARED.
GO FIND YOUR DAD, SWEETIE.
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
NOW TELL ME...
WHO IS IT?
WHO'S THE WATERBENDER?
THERE ARE NO WATERBENDERS HERE.
THE FIRE NATION TOOK THEM
ALL AWAY A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU'RE LYING.
MY SOURCE SAYS
THERE'S ONE WATERBENDER LEFT
IN THE SOUTHERN WATER TRIBE.
WE'RE NOT LEAVING
UNTIL WE FIND THE WATERBENDER.
IF I TELL YOU, DO YOU PROMISE
TO LEAVE THE REST OF
THE VILLAGE ALONE?
MM.
IT'S ME... TAKE ME
AS YOUR PRISONER.
I'M AFRAID I'M NOT
TAKING PRISONERS TODAY.
[GULPS]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
SHE LIED TO YOU.
SHE WAS PROTECTING
THE LAST WATERBENDER.
WHAT?
WHO?
ME!
[GRUNTS]
[WHIMPERS]
I DID A BAD THING, I KNOW I DID,
AND YOU DESERVE REVENGE.
SO WHY DON'T YOU TAKE MY MOTHER?
THAT WOULD BE FAIR.
I ALWAYS WONDERED WHAT KIND OF
PERSON COULD DO SUCH A THING.
BUT NOW THAT I SEE YOU,
I THINK I UNDERSTAND.
THERE'S JUST NOTHING INSIDE YOU,
NOTHING AT ALL.
YOU'RE PATHETIC AND SAD
AND EMPTY.
PLEASE SPARE ME. [WHIMPERS]
BUT AS MUCH AS I HATE YOU...
I JUST CAN'T DO IT.
[YON RHA WHIMPERING...]
[APPA GROANS]
KATARA, ARE YOU OK?
- I'M DOING FINE.
ZUKO TOLD ME WHAT YOU DID.
OR WHAT YOU DIDN'T DO, I GUESS.
I'M PROUD OF YOU.
I WANTED TO DO IT.
I WANTED TO TAKE OUT ALL MY
ANGER AT HIM, BUT I COULDN'T.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
BECAUSE I'M TOO WEAK TO DO IT OR
IF IT'S BECAUSE I'M STRONG
ENOUGH NOT TO.
Aang: YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
FORGIVENESS IS THE FIRST STEP
YOU HAVE TO TAKE
TO BEGIN HEALING.
BUT I DIDN'T FORGIVE HIM...
I'LL NEVER FORGIVE HIM.
BUT I AM READY TO FORGIVE YOU.
Zuko: YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT WHAT KATARA NEEDED.
VIOLENCE WASN'T THE ANSWER.
IT NEVER IS.
THEN I HAVE A QUESTION FOR YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WHEN YOU FACE MY FATHER?
♪