Katara: WATER...
EARTH...
FIRE...
AIR.
LONG AGO, THE FOUR NATIONS
LIVED TOGETHER IN HARMONY.
THEN EVERYTHING CHANGED
WHEN THE FIRE NATION ATTACKED.
ONLY THE AVATAR,
MASTER OF ALL FOUR ELEMENTS,
COULD STOP THEM.
BUT WHEN THE WORLD
NEEDED HIM MOST, HE VANISHED.
100 YEARS PASSED AND MY BROTHER
AND I DISCOVERED THE NEW AVATAR
AN AIRBENDER NAMED AANG.
AND ALTHOUGH HIS AIRBENDING
SKILLS ARE GREAT
HE HAS A LOT TO LEARN BEFORE
HE'S READY TO SAVE ANYONE.
BUT I BELIEVE AANG
CAN SAVE THE WORLD.
♪
Woman: EMBER ISLAND
IS A MAGICAL PLACE.
Ty Lee: DOESN'T YOUR FAMILY HAVE
A HOUSE ON EMBER ISLAND?
Azula: WE USED TO COME EVERY
SUMMER WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
Zuko: THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
Woman: LIKE WAVES WASHING AWAY
THE FOOTPRINTS ON THE SAND
EMBER ISLAND GIVES EVERYONE
A CLEAN SLATE.
EMBER ISLAND REVEALS
THE TRUE YOU.
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
- DOESN'T IT SEEM KIND OF WEIRD
THAT WE'RE HIDING FROM
THE FIRE LORD IN HIS OWN HOUSE?
I TOLD YOU, MY FATHER
HASN'T COME HERE SINCE
OUR FAMILY WAS ACTUALLY HAPPY.
AND THAT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
IT'S THE LAST PLACE ANYONE
WOULD THINK TO LOOK FOR US.
YOU GUYS ARE NOT
GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
THERE'S A PLAY ABOUT US.
WE WERE JUST IN TOWN,
AND WE FOUND THIS POSTER.
Katara: WHAT?
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
LISTEN TO THIS.
Sokka: THE BOY IN THE ICEBERG IS
A NEW PRODUCTION FROM
ACCLAIMED PLAYWRIGHT PUAN TIN
WHO SCOURED THE GLOBE, GATHERING
INFORMATION ON THE AVATAR
FROM THE ICY SOUTH POLE
TO THE HEART OF BA SING SE.
HIS SOURCES INCLUDE
SINGING NOMADS, PIRATES,
PRISONERS OF WAR
AND A SURPRISINGLY KNOWLEDGEABLE
MERCHANT OF CABBAGE.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY
THE CRITICALLY ACCLAIMED
EMBER ISLAND PLAYERS.
UGH.
MY MOTHER USED TO
TAKE US TO SEE THEM.
THEY BUTCHERED "LOVE AMONGST
THE DRAGONS" EVERY YEAR.
SOKKA, DO YOU REALLY THINK IT'S
A GOOD IDEA FOR US TO ATTEND
A PLAY ABOUT OURSELVES?
COME ON.
A DAY AT THE THEATER?
THIS IS THE KIND OF WACKY,
TIME-WASTING NONSENSE
I'VE BEEN MISSING.
[GENERAL CONVERSATION]
HEY, UH, I WANTED TO SIT THERE.
JUST SIT NEXT TO ME.
WHAT'S THE BIG DEAL?
I WAS JUST... I WANTED TO...
OK.
Toph: WHY ARE WE SITTING
IN THE NOSEBLEED SECTION?
MY FEET CAN'T SEE
A THING FROM UP HERE.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL TELL YOUR FEET
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
[♪...]
[GASPING]
[SIGHING]
SOKKA, MY ONLY BROTHER.
WE CONSTANTLY ROAM
THESE ICY SOUTH POLE SEAS
AND YET, NEVER DO WE FIND
ANYTHING FULFILLING.
ALL I WANT IS A FULL FEELING
IN MY STOMACH.
I'M STARVING.
[LAUGHTER]
"Katara": IS FOOD THE ONLY
THING ON YOUR MIND?
WELL, I'M TRYING TO GET IT OUT
OF MY MIND AND INTO MY MOUTH.
I'M STARVING.
[LAUGHTER]
THIS IS PATHETIC.
MY JOKES ARE WAY
FUNNIER THAN THIS.
[LAUGHING]
I THINK HE'S GOT YOU PEGGED.
"Katara": EVERY DAY, THE WORLD
AWAITS A BEACON TO GUIDE US,
YET NONE APPEARS.
STILL, WE CANNOT GIVE UP HOPE,
FOR HOPE IS ALL WE HAVE
AND WE MUST NEVER RELINQUISH IT,
EVEN... EVEN TO
OUR DYING BREATH.
[SOBBING]
WELL, THAT'S JUST SILLY.
I DON'T SOUND LIKE THAT.
[LAUGHING]
OH, MAN, THIS WRITER'S A GENIUS.
"Katara": IT APPEARS TO BE
SOMEONE FROZEN IN ICE,
PERHAPS FOR 100 YEARS.
"Sokka": BUT WHO?
WHO IS THE BOY IN THE ICEBERG?
WATERBEND!
HI-YA!
[CROWD "OOH"ING]
WHO ARE YOU, FROZEN BOY?
[LAUGHING]
I'M THE AVATAR, SILLY,
HERE TO SPREAD JOY AND FUN.
WAIT, IS THAT
A WOMAN PLAYING ME?
[GROWLING]
[GASPING]
AN AIRBENDER.
MY HEART IS SO FULL OF HOPE
THAT IT'S MAKING ME TEAR-BEND.
[SOBBING]
MY STOMACH IS SO EMPTY
THAT IT'S MAKING ME TEAR-BEND.
[SOBBING]
I NEED MEAT!
[GASPING]
BUT WAIT.
IS THAT A PLATTER
OF MEATY DUMPLINGS?
"Sokka": OOH, WHERE, WHERE?
[LAUGHING]
DID I MENTION THAT I'M
AN INCURABLE PRANKSTER?
[LAUGHTER]
I DON'T DO THAT.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I'M LIKE.
AND I'M NOT A WOMAN.
[LAUGHING]
OH, THEY NAILED
YOU, TWINKLE-TOES.
[LAUGHING]
PRINCE ZUKO,
YOU MUST TRY THIS CAKE.
I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO STUFF MY FACE.
I MUST CAPTURE THE AVATAR
TO REGAIN MY HONOR.
WELL, WHILE YOU DO THAT, MAYBE
I'LL CAPTURE ANOTHER SLICE.
[MAKING EATING NOISES]
YOU SICKEN ME.
THEY MAKE ME LOOK TOTALLY
STIFF AND HUMORLESS.
ACTUALLY, I THINK
THAT ACTOR'S PRETTY SPOT-ON.
HOW COULD YOU SAY THAT?
LET'S FORGET ABOUT THE AVATAR
AND GET MASSAGES.
HOW COULD YOU SAY THAT?
HEY, LOOK.
I THINK I FOUND SOMETHING.
IT'S A FLYING RABBIT MONKEY.
I THINK I'LL NAME HIM MOMO.
[LAUGHING]
HI, EVERYBODY.
I LOVE YOU.
[LAUGHTER]
UGH.
DOES THIS DRESS MAKE
MY BUTT LOOK FAT?
[LAUGHTER]
RIDDLES AND CHALLENGES
MUST YOU FACE IF YOU ARE EVER
TO LEAVE THIS PLACE.
[LAUGHING]
[MOANING]
"Sokka": WHY DID YOU
HAVE TO STEAL
THAT WATERBENDING SCROLL?
[SOBBING]: IT JUST GAVE ME
SO MUCH HOPE.
[SOBBING]
THE AVATAR IS MINE!
WAIT, WHO'S COMING?
Male voice: I AM
THE BLUE SPIRIT,
THE SCOURGE OF THE FIRE NATION
HERE TO SAVE THE AVATAR.
"Aang": MY HERO.
[SOBBING]
DON'T CRY, BABY.
JET WILL WIPE OUT
THAT NASTY TOWN FOR YOU.
"Katara": OH, JET.
YOU'RE SO BAD.
[LAUGHING]
LOOK, IT'S THE GREAT DIVIDE,
THE BIGGEST CANYON
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM.
EH, LET'S KEEP FLYING.
DON'T GO, YUE.
YOU'RE THE ONLY WOMAN WHO'S EVER
TAKEN MY MIND OFF OF FOOD.
[GAGGING]
WAIT.
DID YOU HAVE PICKLED FISH
FOR DINNER?
GOODBYE, SOKKA.
I HAVE IMPORTANT MOON DUTIES
TO TAKE CARE OF.
AND YES, I DID
HAVE PICKLED FISH.
[LAUGHING]
YOU NEVER TOLD ME YOU MADE OUT
WITH THE MOON SPIRIT.
SHH, I'M TRYING TO WATCH.
[LAUGHING]
THE AVATAR IS BACK
TO SAVE THE DAY!
YAY!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[GROANING]
[LAUGHING]
Zuko: SO FAR, THIS INTERMISSION
IS THE BEST PART OF THE PLAY.
APPARENTLY, THE PLAYWRIGHT
THINKS I'M AN IDIOT
WHO TELLS BAD JOKES
ABOUT MEAT ALL THE TIME.
YEAH, YOU TELL BAD JOKES
ABOUT PLENTY OF OTHER TOPICS.
I KNOW!
Aang: AT LEAST THE SOKKA ACTOR
KIND OF LOOKS LIKE YOU.
THAT WOMAN PLAYING THE AVATAR
DOESN'T RESEMBLE ME AT ALL.
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU ARE MORE IN TOUCH
WITH YOUR FEMININE SIDE
THAN MOST GUYS.
[GROANING]
Katara: RELAX, AANG.
THEY'RE NOT ACCURATE PORTRAYALS.
IT'S NOT LIKE I'M
A PREACHY CRYBABY
WHO CAN'T RESIST GIVING
OVEREMOTIONAL SPEECHES
ABOUT HOPE ALL THE TIME.
WHAT?
YEAH, THAT'S NOT YOU AT ALL.
LISTEN, FRIENDS.
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT
THE PLAYWRIGHT DID HIS RESEARCH.
I KNOW IT MUST HURT,
BUT WHAT YOU'RE SEEING UP THERE
ON THAT STAGE IS THE TRUTH.
WELL, HERE WE ARE
IN THE EARTH KINGDOM.
I'D BETTER HAVE A LOOK AROUND
TO SEE IF I CAN FIND
AN EARTHBENDING TEACHER.
THIS IS IT.
THIS MUST BE WHERE I COME IN.
"Aang": I FLEW ALL OVER TOWN,
BUT I COULDN'T FIND
A SINGLE EARTHBENDING MASTER.
HERE IT COMES.
YOU CAN'T FIND AN EARTHBENDING
MASTER IN THE SKY.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK UNDERGROUND.
[LAUGHING]
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME'S TOPH,
BECAUSE IT SOUNDS LIKE TOUGH,
AND THAT'S JUST WHAT I AM.
[LAUGHTER]
WAIT A MINUTE.
I SOUND LIKE A GUY.
A REALLY BUFF GUY.
WELL, TOPH, WHAT YOU HEAR
UP THERE IS THE TRUTH.
IT HURTS, DOESN'T IT?
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
I WOULDN'T HAVE CAST IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
[LAUGHING]
AT LEAST IT'S NOT
A FLYING BALD LADY.
SO, YOU'RE BLIND?
[LAUGHING]
I CAN SEE YOU DOING THAT.
I SEE EVERYTHING THAT YOU SEE,
EXCEPT I DON'T SEE LIKE YOU DO.
I RELEASE A SONIC WAVE
FROM MY MOUTH.
[SCREAMING]
THERE.
I GOT A PRETTY GOOD LOOK AT YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
ZUKO, IT'S TIME WE HAD
A TALK ABOUT YOUR HAIR.
IT'S GONE TOO FAR.
MAYBE IT'S BEST IF WE SPLIT UP.
"Zuko": AZULA, MY SISTER,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
YOU CAUGHT ME.
WAIT, WHAT'S THAT?
I THINK IT'S YOUR HONOR.
WHERE?
SHE ESCAPED.
BUT HOW?
IF SHE CONTINUES DRILLING,
THIS WALL WILL COME
DOWN FOR SURE.
[LAUGHING], YES.
CONTINUE DRILLING.
THE CITY OF BA SING SE
CAN HIDE NO LONGER.
[YAWNING]
"Aang": NO, JET.
WHAT DID THEY DO TO YOU?
MUST SERVE EARTH KING.
[GASPING]
MUST DESTROY!
[GRUNTING...]
HELP, [GRUNTING].
DID JET JUST DIE?
YOU KNOW, IT WAS REALLY UNCLEAR.
I HAVE TO ADMIT, PRINCE ZUKO,
I REALLY FIND YOU ATTRACTIVE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
MAKE FUN OF ME.
BUT I MEAN IT.
I'VE HAD EYES FOR YOU SINCE
THE DAY YOU FIRST CAPTURED ME.
"Zuko": WAIT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
THE AVATAR'S GIRL.
[LAUGHING]
THE AVATAR?
WHY, HE'S LIKE
A LITTLE BROTHER TO ME.
[LAUGHING]
I CERTAINLY DON'T THINK OF HIM
IN A ROMANTIC WAY.
BESIDES, HOW COULD HE EVER
FIND OUT ABOUT THIS?
OH, YOU'RE GETTING UP?
CAN YOU GET ME SOME FIRE FLAKES?
OH, AND FIRE GUMMIES.
WELL, MY BROTHER,
WHAT'S IT GOING TO BE?
YOUR NATION,
OR A LIFE OF TREACHERY?
CHOOSE TREACHERY.
IT'S MORE FUN.
NO WAY.
[GRUNTING]
I HATE YOU, UNCLE.
YOU SMELL, AND I HATE YOU
FOR ALL TIME!
YOU DIDN'T REALLY
SAY THAT, DID YOU?
I MIGHT AS WELL HAVE.
[APPLAUSE]
AVATAR STATE.
YIP-YIP.
NOT IF MY LIGHTNING CAN HELP IT.
[SCREAMING]
THE AVATAR IS NO MORE.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Suki: IT SEEMS LIKE EVERY TIME
THERE'S A BIG BATTLE, YOU GUYS
BARELY MAKE IT OUT ALIVE.
I MEAN, YOU GUYS LOSE A LOT.
YOU'RE ONE TO TALK, SUKI.
DIDN'T AZULA TAKE YOU CAPTIVE?
THAT'S RIGHT, SHE DID.
ARE YOU TRYING TO GET
ON MY BAD SIDE?
I'M JUST SAYING.
DOES ANYONE KNOW WHERE AANG IS?
HE LEFT TO GET ME FIRE GUMMIES,
LIKE, 10 MINUTES AGO,
AND I'M STILL WAITING.
I'M GONNA CHECK OUTSIDE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
NO, I'M NOT.
I HATE THIS PLAY.
I KNOW IT'S UPSETTING, BUT IT
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'RE OVERREACTING.
OVERREACTING?
IF I HADN'T BLOCKED MY CHAKRA,
I'D PROBABLY BE IN
THE AVATAR STATE RIGHT NOW.
WHEE!
SUKI, WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
YOU CAN GET ME BACKSTAGE?
I GOT SOME JOKES I WANT
TO GIVE TO THE ACTOR ME.
I'M AN ELITE WARRIOR
WHO'S TRAINED FOR MANY YEARS
IN THE ART OF STEALTH.
I THINK I COULD
GET YOU BACKSTAGE.
GEEZ, EVERYONE'S GETTING
SO UPSET ABOUT THEIR CHARACTERS.
EVEN YOU SEEM
MORE DOWN THAN USUAL,
AND THAT'S SAYING SOMETHING.
YOU DON'T GET IT.
IT'S DIFFERENT FOR YOU.
YOU GET A MUSCLY VERSION
OF YOURSELF TAKING DOWN
10 BAD GUYS AT ONCE
AND MAKING SASSY REMARKS.
YEAH, THAT'S PRETTY GREAT.
BUT FOR ME, IT TAKES
ALL THE MISTAKES
I'VE MADE IN MY LIFE
AND SHOVES THEM BACK IN MY FACE.
MY UNCLE, HE'S ALWAYS
BEEN ON MY SIDE,
EVEN WHEN THINGS WERE BAD.
HE WAS THERE FOR ME.
HE TAUGHT ME SO MUCH,
AND HOW DO I REPAY HIM?
WITH A KNIFE IN HIS BACK.
IT'S MY GREATEST REGRET, AND I
MAY NEVER GET TO REDEEM MYSELF.
YOU HAVE REDEEMED YOURSELF
TO YOUR UNCLE.
YOU DON'T REALIZE IT,
BUT YOU ALREADY HAVE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE I ONCE
HAD A LONG CONVERSATION
WITH THE GUY
AND ALL HE WOULD TALK ABOUT
WAS YOU.
REALLY?
YEAH, AND IT WAS
KIND OF ANNOYING.
OH, SORRY.
BUT IT WAS ALSO VERY SWEET.
ALL YOUR UNCLE WANTED WAS
FOR YOU TO FIND YOUR OWN PATH
AND SEE THE LIGHT.
NOW YOU'RE HERE WITH US.
HE'D BE PROUD.
OW.
WHAT WAS THAT FOR?
THAT'S HOW I SHOW AFFECTION.
YOUR ZUKO COSTUME'S PRETTY GOOD,
BUT YOUR SCAR'S ON
THE WRONG SIDE.
THE SCAR'S NOT ON
THE WRONG SIDE!
HE'S COMING THIS WAY.
CAN I HELP YOU?
ACTUALLY, I THINK
I CAN HELP YOU.
I'M A BIG SOKKA FAN
BUT I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE REPRESENTING HIM QUITE
AS WELL AS YOU COULD BE.
OH, NO.
ANOTHER FAN WITH IDEAS.
JUST HEAR ME OUT.
HERE'S SOMETHING I THINK
THE REAL SOKKA WOULD SAY.
[CLEARING THROAT]
WHAT DOES THE CABBAGE MERCHANT
USE TO FIX HIS CABBAGES?
A CABBAGE PATCH!
[LAUGHING]
THAT'S ACTUALLY PRETTY GOOD.
LET ME SEE THOSE.
[LAUGHING]
A ROCKY RELATIONSHIP.
NOT BAD.
ALSO, DON'T BE AFRAID
TO MAKE UP SOME PHRASES,
ESPECIALLY BEFORE AN ATTACK.
SOMETHING LIKE,
"FLYING KICK-A-POW!"
"Sokka": WHO ARE YOU, ANYWAY?
I'M JUST A GUY WHO LIKES COMEDY.
KATARA, DID YOU REALLY MEAN
WHAT YOU SAID IN THERE?
IN WHERE?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
ON STAGE, WHEN YOU SAID I WAS
JUST LIKE A BROTHER TO YOU
AND YOU DIDN'T HAVE
FEELINGS FOR ME.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
AN ACTOR SAID THAT.
BUT IT'S TRUE, ISN'T IT?
WE KISSED AT THE INVASION,
AND I THOUGHT WE WERE GONNA
BE TOGETHER, BUT WE'RE NOT.
AANG, I DON'T KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE WE'RE IN
THE MIDDLE OF A WAR
AND WE HAVE OTHER THINGS
TO WORRY ABOUT.
THIS ISN'T THE RIGHT TIME.
WELL, WHEN IS THE RIGHT TIME?
AANG, I'M SORRY, BUT RIGHT NOW,
I'M JUST A LITTLE CONFUSED.
I JUST SAID I WAS CONFUSED.
I'M GOING INSIDE.
UGH, I'M SUCH AN IDIOT.
HERE'S WHAT YOU MISSED.
WE WENT TO THE FIRE NATION,
AND YOU GOT BETTER,
AND KATARA WAS THE PAINTED LADY
AND I GOT A SWORD,
AND I THINK COMBUSTION MAN DIED.
OOH, LOOK.
THE INVASION'S ABOUT TO START.
SHH.
I JUST WANT TO LET YOU KNOW,
AANG, THAT I'LL ALWAYS LOVE YOU.
LIKE A BROTHER.
I WOULDN'T WANT IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
HEY, TOPH.
WOULD YOU SAY YOU AND AANG
HAVE A ROCKY RELATIONSHIP?
[LAUGHTER]
[GASPING]
I TOLD HIM TO SAY THAT.
I HOPE EVERYONE'S READY
FOR THE INVASION.
"SLOP-A-POW!"
[LAUGHING]
[LAUGHTER]
"Aang": WE FINALLY MADE IT
TO THE ROYAL PALACE,
BUT NO ONE'S HOME.
ACTUALLY, I'M HOME.
AND I WANT TO JOIN YOU.
I GUESS WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
COME ON.
I GUESS THAT'S IT.
THE PLAY'S CAUGHT UP
TO THE PRESENT NOW.
WAIT.
THE PLAY'S NOT OVER.
BUT IT IS OVER,
UNLESS THIS IS THE FUTURE.
WITH THE ENERGY HARNESSED
FROM THAT COMET, NO ONE WILL
BE ABLE TO STOP THE FIRE NATION!
FATHER, ZUKO AND THE AVATAR
ARE AT THE PALACE.
THEY ARE TRYING TO STOP YOU.
YOU TAKE CARE OF ZUKO.
I SHALL FACE THE AVATAR MYSELF.
AANG, YOU FIND THE FIRE LORD.
I'LL HOLD HER OFF.
YOU ARE NO LONGER MY BROTHER.
YOU ARE AN ENEMY.
NO, I AM THE RIGHTFUL HEIR
TO THE THRONE.
WE'LL SEE.
"Zuko": HONOR!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
SO, YOU HAVE MASTERED
ALL FOUR ELEMENTS?
YEAH, AND NOW,
YOU'RE GOING DOWN.
NO, IT IS YOU
WHO ARE GOING DOWN.
YOU SEE, YOU ARE TOO LATE.
THE COMET IS ALREADY HERE,
AND I'M UNSTOPPABLE!
NO...!
IT IS OVER, FATHER.
WE'VE DONE IT.
YES, WE HAVE DONE IT.
THE DREAMS OF MY FATHER
AND MY FATHER'S FATHER
HAVE NOW BEEN REALIZED.
THE WORLD IS MINE.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Zuko: THAT WASN'T A GOOD PLAY.
I'LL SAY.
- NO KIDDING.
HORRIBLE.
- YOU SAID IT.
- BUT THE EFFECTS WERE DECENT.
♪ MEN VOCALIZING
RHYTHMICALLY... ♪