- KATARA: Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Air.
Long ago, the four nations
lived together in harmony.
Then, everything changed
when the Fire Nation attacked.
Only the Avatar,
master of all four elements,
could stop them.
But when the world
needed him most, he vanished.
A hundred years passed,
and my brother and I discovered
the new Avatar,
an Airbender named Aang.
And although
his airbending skills are great,
he has a lot to learn before
he's ready to save anyone.
- Ugh!
- KATARA: But I believe
Aang can save the world.
♪
- You have mastered
all four elements?
- Yeah, and now
you're goin' down.
- No!
It is you
who are going down.
The comet is already here
and I'm unstoppable!
- The Avatar State
is a defense mechanism
designed to empower you with
the skills and knowledge
of all the past Avatars.
The glow is the combination
of all your past lives,
focusing their energy
through your body.
- I can feel a lot of energy
twisted up around there.
Let me just see
if I can...
- [thunder crashing]
- What happened generations
ago can be resolved now...
by you.
Born in you, along with
all this strife,
is the power to restore
balance to the world.
- After I leave here today,
I'm gonna free
Uncle Iroh from his prison,
and I'm gonna beg
for his forgiveness.
But I've come to an even
more important decision.
I'm gonna join the Avatar,
and I'm going to
help him defeat you.
Where is my uncle?
- He busted himself out.
- Sokka!
It's you!
- AANG: We kissed
at the invasion,
and I thought we were
gonna be together,
but we're not.
- Aang...
I don't know.
- You miscalculated.
I love Zuko
more than I fear you.
- No, you miscalculated!
You should have
feared me more!
♪
- [heavy thud]
- You were right about
what Katara needed.
Violence wasn't the answer.
- It never is.
- Then I have
a question for you.
What are you gonna do
when you face my father?
- [dramatic music]
♪
- More ferocious!
Imagine striking through
your opponent's heart.
- [groans]
I'm trying.
- Now let me hear you roar
like tiger-dillo.
- [quiet roar]
- That sounded pathetic.
I said, roar!
- [roaring]
- [frightened chattering]
- Who wants a nice cool
glass of watermelon juice?
- Ooh, ooh, me, me, me!
- Hey, your lesson's not
over yet! Get back here!
- Come on, Zuko,
just take a break.
What's the big deal?
- Fine.
If you wanna
lounge around
like a bunch of snail sloths
all day, then go ahead!
- AANG: [slurping]
- Maybe Zuko's right.
Sitting around the house
has made us pretty lazy.
But I know just the thing
to change that--
Beach party!
- ♪
♪
- Check out my Appa
sand-sculpture.
- APPA:
[bellowing]
- Not, bad baldy.
But I've been working
on my sandbending.
You're gonna love this.
- ♪
- Whoa!
Wow, you even made a little
Earth King and Bosco.
- Try and top
that, Sokka.
- Ta-da!
- AANG: Is that
a blubbering blob-monster?
- No, it's Suki!
- BOTH:
[laughing]
- Suki, we'll
all understand
if you break with
him up over this.
- I think it's sweet.
- [smooching]
- But it doesn't
even look like--
[screams]
- ♪
- What are you doing?
- Teaching you a lesson.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- What happened?
- Zuko's gone crazy!
I made a sand sculpture
of Suki and he destroyed it!
Oh, and he's
attacking Aang.
- ♪
♪
- Get a grip before I blast
you off this roof!
- Go ahead and do it.
- ♪
♪
- Enough!
- ♪
- [wood splintering]
- ZUKO:
[grunting]
[groans]
- What's wrong with you?
You could have hurt Aang.
- What's wrong with me?
What's wrong with
all of you?
How can you sit around
having beach parties
when Sozin's comet
is only three days away?
Why are you all looking
at me like I'm crazy?
- About Sozin's comet--
I was actually gonna
wait to fight the Firelord
until after it came.
- After?
- I'm not ready.
I need more time
to master firebending.
- And, frankly,
your earthbending
could still use
some work, too.
- So, you all knew
Aang was gonna wait?
- Honestly, if Aang tries to
fight the Firelord right now,
he's gonna lose.
No offence.
- The whole point of
fighting the Firelord
before the comet
was to stop the Fire Nation
from winning the war.
But they pretty much won the war
when they took Ba Sing Se.
Things can't get any worse.
- You're wrong.
It's about to get worse
than you can even imagine.
The day before the eclipse,
my father asked me to attend
an important war meeting.
It was what I'd dreamed about
and wanted for so many years.
My father had finally
accepted me back.
- Welcome, Prince Zuko.
We waited for you.
General Shinu,
your report.
- Thank you, sir.
Ba Sing Se is still
under our control,
however, Earthbender
rebellions have prevented us
from achieving total victory
in the Earth Kingdom.
- What is
your recommendation?
- Our army is spread too thin,
but once the eclipse is over,
and the invasion defeated,
we should transfer more domestic
forces into the Earth Kingdom.
- Mmm...
Prince Zuko, you've been among
the Earth Kingdom commoners.
Do you think that
adding more troops
will stop these rebellions?
- The people of the Earth
Kingdom are proud and strong.
They can endure anything
as long as they have hope.
- Yes, you're right.
We need to destroy
their hope.
- Well, that's not
exactly what I--
- I think you should take
their precious hope,
and the rest of their land
and burn it all to the ground.
- Yes, yes,
you're right Azula.
Sozin's comet
is almost upon us,
And on that day,
it will endow us
with the strength
and power of a hundred suns.
No bender will stand
a chance against us.
- What are suggesting, sir?
- When the comet last came,
my grandfather, Firelord Sozin,
used it to wipe
out the Air Nomads.
Now, I will use its power
to end the Earth Kingdom--
permanently!
From our airships we will
rain fire over their lands,
a fire that will
destroy everything,
and out of the ashes,
a new world will be born,
a world in which all
the lands are Fire Nation,
and I am the supreme
ruler of everything!
- ALL:
[applauding]
- ZUKO:
I wanted to speak out
against this
horrifying plan,
but I'm ashamed
to say I didn't.
My whole life,
I've struggled
to gain my father's
love and acceptance.
But once I had it,
I realized I'd lost myself
getting there.
I'd forgotten who I was.
- I can't believe this.
- I always knew the Firelord
was a bad guy.
But his plan
is just pure evil.
- What am I gonna do?
- I know you're scared.
And I know you're not
ready to save the world.
But if you don't defeat the
Firelord before the comet comes,
there won't be a world
to save anymore.
- [dramatic music]
- Why didn't you tell me about
your dad's crazy plan sooner?
- I didn't think I had to.
I assumed you were still gonna
fight him before the comet.
No one told me you
decided to wait.
- This is bad.
This is really,
really bad.
- Aang, you don't have
to do this alone.
- Yeah, if we all fight
the Firelord together,
we've got a shot
at taking him down.
- All right!
Team Avatar is back!
Air.
Water.
Earth.
Fire.
Fan and sword.
- Fighting the Firelord
is gonna be the hardest thing
we've ever done together.
But I wouldn't wanna
do it any other way.
- ALL EXCEPT ZUKO:
[laughing]
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Get over here, Zuko.
Being part of the group
also means being part
of group hugs.
- APPA:
[bellowing]
- [heavy thud]
- There is one technique
you need to know
before facing
my father--
how to redirect
lightning.
If you let the energy
in your own body flow,
the lightning will
follow it.
You turn your opponents'
energy against them.
- That's like waterbending.
- Exactly.
My uncle invented
this technique himself
by studying Waterbenders.
- So, have you ever
redirected lightning before?
- Once...
against my father.
- What did it feel like?
- Exhilarating.
- [electrical zapping]
- But terrifying.
- [explosion]
- You feel so powerful holding
that much energy in your body,
but you know if you make
the wrong move--it's over.
- [laughs]
Well, not over-over.
I mean,
there is always Katara
and a little spirit water
action, am I right?
- Actually, I used it all
up after Azula shot you.
- Oh.
- You'll have to take Firelord's
life before he takes yours.
- Yeah, I'll just
do that.
- SOKKA: Gather around,
Team Avatar.
In order to take
out the Firelord,
or, in this case,
the Melonlord,
our timing has
to be perfect.
First, Suki and I will
draw his fire.
Then Katara and Zuko charge in
with some liquidy hot offence,
and while the Melonlord
is distracted,
Aang swoops in and "bam,"
he delivers the final blow.
- Uh, what about me?
- For now, you're
the Melonlord's forces.
- So, I get to chuck
flaming rocks at all of you?
- Whatever makes the training
field more realistic.
- Sweetness.
Mwa-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
- ♪
♪
- [flames crackling]
- Watch it, Toph!
- I am not Toph,
I am Melonlord!
Mwa-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
- ♪
- Now, Aang.
- What are you waiting for?
Take him out!
- I can't.
- What's wrong with you?
If this was
the real deal,
you'd be shot full
of lightning right now.
- I'm sorry, but it just
didn't feel right.
I didn't feel
like myself.
- [watermelon splats]
- There!
That's how it's done.
- [nibbling]
- I have a surprise
for everyone!
- I knew it! You did have
a secret thing with Haru!
- Uh...no.
I was looking for cooking pots
in the attic and I found this.
Look at baby Zuko!
Isn't he cute?
- ALL EXCEPT ZUKO:
[laughing]
- Oh, lighten up.
I'm just teasing.
That's not me.
It's my father.
- But he looks so sweet
and innocent.
- Well, that sweet little kid
grew up to be a monster.
And the worst father in
the history of fathers.
- AANG: But he's still
a human being.
- You're going to
defend him?
- No, I agree with you.
Firelord Ozai
is a horrible person,
and the world will probably
be better off without him,
but there's gotta
be another way.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Maybe we can make
some big pots of glue
and then I can
use gluebending
to stick his arms
and legs together
so he can't bend anymore.
- Yeah, then you can show
him his baby pictures
and all those happy memories
will make him good again.
- Do you really think
that would work?
- No!
- [heavy sigh]
This goes against everything
I learned from the monks.
I can't just go around wiping
out people I don't like.
- Sure, you can.
You're the Avatar.
If it's in the name
of keeping balance,
I'm pretty sure the universe
will forgive you.
- This isn't
a joke, Sokka!
None of you understand
the position I'm in!
- Aang, we do understand.
It's just--
- Just what, Katara, what?
- We're trying to help.
- When you figure out a way
for me to beat the Firelord
without taking his life,
I'd love to hear it!
- Aang, don't walk
away from this.
- Let him go.
He needs time to sort
it out by himself.
- ♪
- [chattering]
- Hey, Momo.
I don't suppose you know
what I should do.
- [squawks]
- I didn't think so.
- ♪
- MEN: [deep-toned
hypnotic chanting]
- ♪
- [hypnotic chanting
continues]
- ♪
- [hypnotic chanting
continues]
- ♪
- SOKKA:
Okay, that's everything.
- No, it's not.
Where's Aang?
- Aang? Aang?
- Come on, lazy bones,
let's go!
- [door creaks, thuds]
- He left his staff.
That's so strange.
- Aang's not in a house.
Let's check the beach.
- SOKKA: Look! There's
his footprints.
The trail ends here.
- So, he went for a midnight
swim and never came back?
- Maybe he was captured.
- I don't think so.
There's no sign of a struggle.
- I bet he ran away again.
- Unh-unh. He left behind
his glider and Appa.
- Then what do you think's
happened to him,
oh, sleuthy one?
- It's pretty obvious.
Aang mysteriously disappears
before an important battle?
He's definitely on
a spirit world journey.
- But if he was, wouldn't
his body still be here?
- Oh, yeah,
I forgot about that.
- Then he's gotta be
somewhere on Ember Island.
Let's split up
and look for him.
- I'm going with Zuko!
What?
Everyone else went on a life-
changing field-trip with Zuko.
Now, it's my turn.
- ♪
- CROWD:
[chanting "Aang! Aang!"]
[chanting continues]
- Avatar State, yip-yip!
- CROWD: [cheering]
- BOTH:
[growling]
- TOPH: And then when I was
nine, I ran away again.
- Uh-huh.
- I know I shouldn't complain.
My parents gave me
everything I ever asked for.
But they never gave the one
thing that I really wanted--
their love,
you know what I mean?
- [groans]
Look, I know you
had a rough childhood.
But we should really
focus on finding Aang.
- This is the worst
field trip ever.
[blows air]
- Judging by the looks
on your faces,
I'm guessing you guys
didn't find Aang, either.
- No.
It's like he just
disappeared.
- Hey, wait a minute.
Has anyone noticed that
Momo is missing, too?
- Oh, no! I knew it
was only a matter of time!
Appa ate Momo!
Momo, I'm coming
for you, buddy!
- Sokka, Appa didn't eat Momo.
He's probably with Aang.
- That's just what Appa
wants you to think.
- ZUKO: Get out of
the bison's mouth, Sokka.
We have a real problem here.
Aang is nowhere to be found and
the comet is only two days away.
- What should we do, Zuko?
- I don't know.
Why are you all
looking at me?
- Well, you are kind of
the expert on tracking Aang.
- Yeah, if anyone's
got experience
hunting the Avatar,
it's you.
- Zuko, I don't wanna tell
you how to do your job,
but why we are heading
towards the Earth Kingdom?
There's no way
Aang's there.
- Just trust me.
- ♪
♪
- Come on,
slowpokes, faster!
- ♪
♪
- Sorry I'm late, Father.
Good palanquin bearers are
so hard to come by these days.
So, is everything ready
for our departure?
- There has been a change
of plans, Azula.
- What?
- I've decided to lead the fleet
of airships to Ba Sing Se alone.
You will remain here
in the Fire Nation.
- But, I thought we were
going to do this together.
- My decision is final.
- You...you can't
treat me like this!
You can't treat
me like Zuko!
- Azula, silence yourself.
- But it was my idea to burn
everything to the ground.
I deserve to be
by your side!
- Azula!
Listen to me.
I need you here to watch
over the homeland.
It's a very important job that
I can only entrust to you.
- Really?
- And for your loyalty,
I've decided to declare
you the new Firelord.
- Firelord Azula?
It does seems appropriate.
But, what about you?
- Firelord Ozai is no more.
Just as the world will
be reborn in fire,
I shall be reborn as
the supreme ruler of the world.
From this moment on,
I will be known as...
The Phoenix King!
♪
- TAVERN PATRONS:
[shouting mixed comments]
- And the reason
you brought us
to a seedy Earth Kingdom
tavern is what now?
- Jun.
- MAN:
[groans]
- SOKKA: Oh, yeah,
that weird bounty hunter
with the giant mole.
- KATARA: Mole?
Her skin is flawless.
- SOKKA: No, she has this
giant mole-creature
she rides around on.
- The Shirshu.
It's the only animal that
can track Aang's scent
anywhere in the world.
It's the one shot
we have of finding him.
- MAN:
[grunting]
- I don't know who this
Jun lady is, but I like her.
- [chattering]
[licking]
- [groaning]
Hey, Momo. I just had
the strangest dream.
Wait!
- [chattering]
- ♪
- AANG:
Where are we?
- [dramatic music]
- ♪
- Hey, I remember her.
She helped you attack us.
- Yep. Back in
the good old days.
- JUN: Oh, great,
it's Prince Pouty.
Where's your
creepy grandpa?
- He's my uncle.
And he's not here.
- I see you worked things
out with your girlfriend.
- I'm not his girlfriend!
- She's not my girlfriend!
- Okay, okay. Sheesh.
I was only teasing.
So what do you want?
- I need your help
finding the Avatar.
- Hm, doesn't
sound too fun.
- Does the end of the world
sound like more fun?
- APPA:
[growling]
[slurping]
- Nyla?
- [chomping]
- Whose my little
snuffly-wuffly?
Whoa! Careful there!
Okay, so who's got something
with the Avatar's scent on it?
- I have Aang's staff.
- [sniffing]
[sniffing]
[quiet growling]
- Well, what does
that mean?
- It means your
friend's gone.
- We know he's gone.
That's why we're
trying to find him.
- No, I mean
he's gone-gone.
He doesn't exist.
- [chattering]
- Where are we, Momo?
Maybe I'm in
the Spirit World?
But, wait, you can see me.
We could both be in
the Spirit World.
Nope, my bending works.
Maybe if we climb to
the top of the island,
we can figure out
where we are.
- What do you mean
Aang doesn't exist?
Do you mean he's,
you know, dead?
- Nope, we could find
him if he were dead.
Oh, it's a real
headscratcher.
See ya.
- Helpful. Real helpful.
- Wait, I have another idea.
There's only one
other person in this world
who can help us
face the Firelord.
I'll be right back
with a smell sample.
- [insects buzzing]
- You saved your
uncle's sweaty sandal?
- I think it's
kind of sweet.
- [sniffing]
- Let's do this.
- ZUKO:
Hey, wait up!
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [heavy thud]
- SOKKA: We're going
to Ba Sing Se?
- JUN: Your uncle is
somewhere beyond the wall.
Nyla is getting twitchy,
so it can't be too far.
Good luck.
- It's been a long day.
Let's camp and start
our search again at dawn.
- [bird twittering]
- It's a hexagon.
- [chattering]
- It doesn't seem
like normal rock.
It's not made of earth.
This is so strange.
I wish some help right now.
I wish I had Roku.
I do have Roku!
- [slowly inhaling, exhaling]
- ♪
- You're right, Aang.
All the past Avatars,
all their experience and wisdom
is available to you,
if you look deep
inside yourself.
- So, where am I, Roku?
What is this place?
- I don't know, Aang.
But I see that you are lost in
more ways than one right now.
- I am.
I need to figure
out what to do
once I face
the Firelord.
- SOKKA: [snoring
loudly, sighing]
- Huh?
- ♪
- APPA:
[bellowing]
- ♪
- Well, look who's here.
[snorting laughter]
- Everyone expects me to
take the Firelord's life.
But I just don't know
if I can do that.
- In my life, I tried to be
disciplined and show restraint,
but it backfired
when Firelord Sozin
took advantage of
my restraint and mercy.
If had been more decisive,
and acted sooner,
I could have stopped Sozin
and stopped the war
before it started.
I offer you
this wisdom, Aang.
You must be decisive.
- ♪
- TOPH:
What's going on?
We're surrounded
by old people.
- KATARA:
Not just any old people,
these are great masters
and friends of ours.
Pakku.
- It is respectful to
bow to an old master.
But how about a hug
for your new grandfather?
- That's so exciting!
- SOKKA: [gasps]
- You and Gran Gran
must be so happy
to have found
each other again.
- I made her a new betrothal
necklace and everything.
- Welcome to the family,
Gramp-Gramp!
- You can still
just call me Pakku.
- How about Gramp-Pakku?
- No.
- And this was Aang's
first firebending teacher.
- Jeong-Jeong.
- Master Piandao.
- Hello, Sokka.
- So, wait, how do you
all know each other?
- All old people know each
other, don't you know that?
[snorting laughter]
- We're all are part of the same
ancient secret society,
a group that transcends the
divisions of the four nations.
- The Order
of the White Lotus.
- That's the one.
- The White Lotus has always
been about philosophy,
and beauty, and truth.
But about a month ago,
a call went out
that we were needed for
something important.
- It came from
our Grand Lotus, your uncle,
Iroh of the Fire Nation.
- Well, that's who
we're looking for.
- Then we'll take you to him.
- Wait, someone's missing
from your group,
someone very important.
Where's Momo?
- He's gone
and so is Aang.
- Oh, well, so long
as they have each other,
I'm sure we have
nothing to worry about.
Let's go!
[snorting laughter]
- [chattering]
- Avatar Kyoshi,
I need your wisdom.
- ♪
- In my day,
Chin The Conqueror
threatened to throw
the world out of balance.
I stopped him and the world
entered a great era of peace.
- AANG: But you didn't
really kill Chin.
Technically, he fell
to his own doom
because he was too stubborn
to get out of the way.
- Personally, I don't
really see the difference.
But I assure you,
I would have done whatever
it took to stop Chin.
I offer you this
wisdom, Aang.
Only justice will
bring peace.
- I knew I shouldn't
have asked Kyoshi.
- SOKKA: So, Bumi,
how did you end up escaping
your imprisonment
in Omashu?
- Escape?
I didn't escape.
Everybody else escaped.
There I was,
back in Omashu,
waiting for
just the right moment.
I didn't know
what or when,
but I knew I'd know
it when I knew it.
An eclipse!
That'll do it!
[straining]
- ♪
- What do you think
you're doing?
[grunts]
- Taking back my city.
You've got no firepower
and it's payback time!
- ♪
♪
- [straining]
- ♪
- [snorting laughter]
[chomps, chewing]
- Wow, you took back your whole
city all by yourself.
- BUMI:
So what about you, guys?
Did you do anything interesting
on the day of the eclipse?
- Nah.
- No, not really.
- I need to look
deep inside myself.
- ♪
- I am Avatar Kuruk.
When I was young,
I was always a "go with
the flow" kind of Avatar.
People seemed to work
out their own problems,
and there was peace
and good times in the world.
But then, I lost
the woman I loved
to Koh, the face stealer.
It was my fault.
If I had been more attentive
and more active,
I could have saved her.
Aang, you must actively
shape your own destiny,
and the destiny
of the world.
- ♪
- [boulder lowers]
- Well, here we are.
Welcome to old people camp.
- Where? Where is he?
- Your uncle's in there,
Prince Zuko.
- ♪
- Are you okay?
- No, I'm not okay.
My uncle hates me,
I know it.
He loved me and supported me
in every way he could,
and I still turned
against him.
How can I even face him?
- Zuko, you're sorry for
what you did, right?
- More sorry than I've
been about anything
in my entire life.
- Then he'll forgive you.
He will.
- ♪
- [heavy sigh]
Uncle...
- [loud snoring]
- ♪
- AANG: All these
past Avatars,
they keep telling me
I'm gonna have to do it.
They don't get it.
- [chattering]
- You're right, maybe
an Air Nomad Avatar
will understand where
I'm coming from.
- [chattering]
- I know you can't
really talk.
Pretending you can
just helps me think.
- [chattering]
- I'm going to pretend
I didn't pretend to hear that.
- ♪
- I am Avatar Yangchen,
young Airbender.
- Avatar Yangchen,
the monks always taught me
that all life is sacred,
even the life of
the tiniest spider-fly
caught in its own web.
- Yes, all life is sacred.
- I know. I'm even
a vegetarian.
I've always tried
to solve my problems
by being quick or clever,
and I've only had to use
violence for necessary defense,
and I've certainly never
used it to take a life.
- Avatar Aang, I know that
you're a gentle spirit,
and the monks have
taught you well,
but this isn't about you.
This is about the world.
- But the monks taught me,
that I have to detach myself
from the world
so my spirit could be free.
- Many great and wise Air Nomads
have detached themselves
and achieved spiritual
enlightenment.
But the Avatar
can never do it,
because your sole duty
is to the world.
Here is my wisdom for you--
selfless duty calls
you to sacrifice
your own spiritual needs
and do whatever it takes
to protect the world.
- [chattering]
- I guess I don't have
a choice, Momo.
I have to kill
the Firelord.
- ♪
- [snoring loudly]
Hmmm...
[yawning loudly]
- Uncle, I know you must have
mixed feelings about seeing me.
But I want you to know
I am so, so sorry, Uncle.
I am so sorry and ashamed
of what I did.
I don't know how I can ever
make it up to you, but I--
- ♪
- How can you forgive
me so easily?
I thought you would
be furious with me.
- I was never angry
with you.
I was sad, because I was
afraid you'd lost your way.
- I did lose my way.
- But you've found
it again...
and you did it
by yourself,
and I am so happy you
found your way here.
- It wasn't that
hard, Uncle.
You have a pretty
strong scent.
- SQUIRREL:
[chattering]
- BIRDS:
[twittering]
- [distant rumbling]
- [loud yawn]
- [louder rumbling]
- Wait, is it just me or are
those mountains getting bigger?
- [chattering]
- They're not getting larger,
they're getting closer.
- [chattering]
- The whole island
is moving!
- ♪
- [chattering]
- [gasping for air]
- It's amazing, Momo!
The biggest animal
in the world!
I've gotta swim
around and find its face.
- ♪
- ZUKO: Uncle, you're the only
person other than the Avatar
who can possibly
defeat the Fatherlord.
- You mean the Firelord?
- That's what I just said.
- Hmmm...
- We need you to
come with us.
- No, Zuko.
It won't turn out well.
- You can beat him
and we'll be there to help.
- Even if I did defeat Ozai,
and I don't know
that I could,
it would be the wrong
way to end a war.
History will see it as just
more senseless violence,
a brother killing a brother
to grab power.
The only way for this
war to end peacefully
is for the Avatar
to defeat the Firelord.
- And then...then would
you come and take
your rightful place
on the throne?
- No. Someone new must
take the throne--
an idealist with a pure heart
and unquestionable honor.
It has to be you,
Prince Zuko.
- Unquestionable honor?
But I've made
so many mistakes.
- Yes, you have.
You've struggled
and you've suffered,
but you have always
followed your own path.
You restored
your own honor,
and only you can restore
the honor of the Fire Nation.
- I'll try, Uncle.
- Well, what if Aang
doesn't come back?
- Sozin's Comet is arriving
and our destinies are upon us.
Aang will face
the Firelord.
When I was a boy,
I had a vision
that I would one day
take Ba Sing Se.
Only now do I see
that my destiny
is to take it back
from the Fire Nation,
so the Earth Kingdom
can be free again.
- That's why you gathered
the members of the White Lotus.
- Yes.
Zuko, you must return
to the Fire Nation,
so that when
the Firelord falls,
you can assume the throne
and restore peace and order.
But Azula will be there
waiting for you.
- I can handle Azula.
- Not alone.
You'll need help.
- You're right.
Katara, how would you like to
help me put Azula in her place?
- It would be my pleasure.
- What about us?
What's our destiny today?
- What do you think it is?
- I think that even though
we don't know where Aang is,
we need to do everything we can
to stop the airship fleet.
- And that means, when Aang
does face the Firelord,
we'll be right there
if he needs us.
- ♪
- Nothing runs
faster over land
or swims quicker
than a giant eel-hound.
The airship base
is on a small island
just off the Earth
Kingdom shore.
You should be able
to intercept the fleet
within a day's journey.
- Thank you, master.
- ♪
- So, if I'm gonna be Firelord
after the war's over,
what are you gonna do?
- After I reconquer
Ba Sing Se,
I am going to
reconquer my tea shop
and I am going to play
Pai Sho every day.
- Goodbye, General Iroh.
- Goodbye, everyone.
Today, destiny is
our friend. I know it.
- ♪
♪
[dramatic music]
- A lion-turtle.
Maybe you can help me.
Everyone, even
my own past lives
are expecting me to
end someone's life.
But I don't know
if I can do it.
- LION-TURTLE: The true mind
can weather all the lies
and illusions
without being lost.
The true heart can tough
the poison of hatred
without being harmed.
Since beginning-less time,
darkness thrives in the void,
but always yields
to purifying light.
♪
- Wait for him.
He will come.
♪
- It's time for this
world to end in fire
and for a new world
to be born from the ashes.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [comet roaring]
- APPA:
[bellowing]
- Zuko, don't worry.
We can take Azula.
- I'm not worried
about her.
I'm worried about Aang.
What if he doesn't have the guts
to take out my father?
What if he loses?
- Aang won't lose.
He's gonna come back.
He has to.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [tooth crunches]
[spits]
What am I holding?
- A cherry pit, Princess.
- Correct.
And what day is this?
- It is the day
of your coronation.
- Yes, it is.
So, please, tell me why,
on the most important
day of my life,
you decided to leave
a pit in my cherry?
- It wasn't a decision,
it was just a small mistake.
- Small?
Do you realize what
could have happened
if I hadn't sensed
the pit in time?
- I suppose you
could have choked?
- Yes, then you understand
the severity of your crime.
- I understand, Princess.
Please, forgive me.
- Oh, very well.
Since it is a special day,
I will show mercy.
You are banished.
Leave this palace
immediately.
What are you
all looking at?
I have two feet
that need scrubbing.
And make sure you get
in between the toes.
I won't have my
first day as Firelord
marred by poor
foot hygiene.
- It's weird to say, but the
comet actually looks beautiful.
- Too bad the Firelord's about
to use it to destroy the world.
- ♪
♪
- SOKKA: We're too late!
The fleet's already taking off!
- TOPH: Then we're
taking off, too.
Where's the closest airship?
- It's right--
- ALL:
[gasping]
- ♪
- [grunts]
♪
- You sent for us,
Princess?
Is everything all right?
- Actually, everything's
not all right.
Do you know how long
it took you to get here?
- Uh, few minutes,
I guess.
- AZULA:
Five, to be precise--
in which time an assassin
could have snuck in,
done away with me,
and been on his merry way.
- My apologies, Princess.
- Is this how you plan to
treat your new Firelord--
with tardiness
and disloyalty?
- The Dai Lee would
never betray you.
- And I'm sure that's just
what you told Long Feng
before you turned
against him and joined me.
You're all banished!
- But--
- AZULA:
Goodbye!
Please send in the next
group on your way out.
- ♪
- Shhhh...
- [rapping on metal door]
- [metal door slams]
- ♪
- Oh!
- [grunting, groaning]
- ♪
- That's how it's done.
- SOKKA: Good work, Toph.
Time to take control
of the ship.
Take the wheel.
- That's a great idea.
Let the blind girl steer
the giant airship.
- I was talking to Suki.
- That would make
a lot more sense.
- What are we gonna do
about the rest of the crew?
- Take us down closer
to the water.
I've got an idea.
[clears throat]
Attention, crew,
this is your
captain speaking.
Everyone please report to
the bomb bay immediately,
for hot cakes
and sweet cream.
We have a very special
birthday to celebrate.
- ♪
- [mixed conversations]
- Hey, I'm Quin Lee.
I work up in
Communications.
- Oh, hi.
I work down in
the engine room.
That's probably why
we've never met before.
Big airship, you know?
- Uh-huh.
- Yep.
- So, do you know
whose birthday it is?
- I can't believe that captain
remembered my birthday!
He really does care!
- CREW:
[screaming]
- [water splashing]
- CREW:
[gasping for air]
- Happy birthday.
- ♪
- Firelord Ozai,
here we come.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- Azula, we heard
what happened.
- Why have you banished
all your servants...
- ...all your
Dai Lee agents...
- ...and the Imperial
Firebenders?
- None of them
could be trusted.
Sooner or later they all
would have betrayed me--
just like Mai
and Ty Lee did.
- BOTH: Azula, we are concerned
for you and your well-being.
- My father asked you to come
here and talk to me didn't he?
He thinks I can't handle
the responsibility
of being Firelord.
But I will be
the greatest leader
in Fire Nation history.
- I'm sure you will.
But considering everything
that's happened today...
- ...perhaps it's best if
you postpone your coronation.
- What? Which one
of you just said that?
- What a shame.
There's only one way
to resolve this.
You two must duel
each other.
I order you to fight
an Agni Kai.
- But...
- BOTH: We're not Firebenders.
- All right, fine.
Lo, you're banished.
Li, you can stay.
- But, I'm Li.
So who is banished?
- ♪
- Ba Sing Se, the Order of
the White Lotus is here.
- Here, to set you free.
- Only once every
hundred years,
can a Firebender experience
this kind of power.
- [comet roaring]
- ♪
- [roaring]
♪
- [discordant music]
- [frustrated groan]
All right, hair,
it's time to face your doom.
- [dramatic music]
- [scissors snip]
- What a shame. You always
had such beautiful hair.
- What are you doing here?
- I didn't want to miss
my own daughter's coronation.
- Don't pretend
to act proud.
I know what you
really think of me.
You think I'm a monster.
- I think you're confused.
All your life you've used
fear to control people.
Like your friends,
Mai and Ty Lee.
- But what choice do I have?
Trust is for fools.
Fear is the only
reliable way.
Even you fear me.
- No, I love you, Azula.
I do.
- ♪
- [grunt of effort]
- [mirror shatters]
- AZULA:
[quietly sobbing]
- ♪
- [inhaling, exhaling]
- We're not gonna catch
up to him in time!
- No.
- ♪
♪
- [chattering]
- Momo, time for
you to go.
- [chattering]
- [inhaling, exhaling]
- ♪
♪
- What just happened?
- It's Aang!
He's back!
- [dramatic music]
- ♪
- After generations of
Firelords failed to find you,
now the universe delivers you
to me as an act of providence.
- Please listen to me.
We don't have to fight.
You have the power to end it
here and stop what you're doing.
- You are right.
I do have the power.
I have all the power
in the world!
- ♪
♪
- Go, Aang!
Airbending slice!
- Shouldn't we be
helping him?
- The Firelord
is Aang's fight.
We need to stay focused
on stopping that fleet
from burning down
the Earth Kingdom.
- And how do we do that,
Captain Boomerang?
I can't see outside of
this floating hunk of metal.
- Airship slice!
- ♪
♪
- Whoa, that's a lot
of fire, isn't it?
- ♪
♪
- SOKKA: It's gonna
be a rough ride.
We need to get to the top
of this thing, fast.
- [objects rattling]
- Then what?
- Watch each other's backs,
and if we make it that far--
I'll let you know.
[kisses]
- ♪
♪
- SUKI:
[gasps]
[screaming]
- Suki!
- [dramatic music]
- SUKI:
I'm okay!
Just finish the mission!
- No.
- Sokka, I think
we've gotta...
- SOKKA &amp; TOPH:
...jump!
- [explosion]
- SOKKA &amp; TOPH:
[screaming]
- ♪
- By decree of
Phoenix King Ozai,
I now crown
you Firelord--
- What are you
waiting for?
Do it!
- APPA:
[bellowing]
[heavy thud]
- Sorry, but you're not gonna
become Firelord today.
I am.
- [mocking laughter]
You're hilarious.
- And you're going down.
- Wait. You want
to be Firelord?
Fine, let's settle this.
Just you and me, brother,
the showdown that was
always meant to be--
Agni Kai!
- You're on.
- What are you doing?
She's playing you.
She knows she can't
take us both,
so she's trying
to separate us.
- I know, but I can
take her this time.
- KATARA: But even you
admitted to your uncle
that would need
help facing Azula.
- ZUKO: There's something
off about her.
I can't explain it,
but she's slipping.
And this way, no one else
has to get hurt.
- ♪
- I'm sorry it has to end
this way, brother.
- No, you're not.
- ♪
♪
- [heavy thud]
- AANG: [groans]
[groaning]
- ♪
- [electrical zapping]
[electrical zapping]
- [gasping]
[screams]
- ♪
- AANG: [groaning]
- Mmm...
- ♪
- [gasping]
♪
- [panting]
- ♪
♪
- [groans]
[groaning]
[panting]
- No lightning today?
What's the matter?
Afraid I'll redirect it?
- Oh, I'll show
you lightning!
- [thunder crashing]
- [inhaling, exhaling]
- [electrical zapping]
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [electrical zapping]
- ♪
- [slow motion]
No-o-o-o!
- ♪
- [thunder crashing]
- [electrical zapping]
- ZUKO:
[groaning]
- Zuko!
- [electrical zapping]
- [evil laughter]
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [grunts]
- ♪
- [laughing]
You're weak!
Just like the rest
of your people!
They did not deserve to exist
in this world, in my world!
Prepare to join them.
Prepare to...die!
♪
- Come on out, Avatar!
You can't hide
in there forever!
♪
- Toph, metalbend
the rudder,
so it's jammed
in the turning position.
The ship will spiral
and slam into the others.
- Got it.
[spitting into hands]
[straining]
♪
- CREW:
[gasps]
♪
- Have I ever mentioned
how sweet it is
that you invented
metalbending?
- You could stand
to mention it more.
♪
- SOKKA &amp; TOPH:
[screaming]
[screaming continues]
- TOPH:
[screaming]
- SOKKA: Oh!
[straining]
My leg!
Hang on, Toph.
- Aye-aye, Captain.
- ♪
- [grunt of effort]
- [gasps]
Bye, space sword.
- ♪
- [straining]
I don't think Boomerang
is coming back, Toph.
It's looks like
this is the end.
- CREW:
[gasping]
- [metal thuds, grinds]
- ♪
- How did that happen?
Did Boomerang come back?
- No, Suki did.
- ♪
♪
- [electrical zapping]
- AANG: [screams]
- ♪
- Come on out, little boy.
You're about to be--
[gasps]
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [grunting]
[heavy thud, groans]
- ♪
- AANG:
[roaring]
- ♪
- [gasping]
♪
- Huh!
- [cannons firing]
- Ah!
[straining]
[grunts of effort]
- ♪
- [metal clanking]
- MEN:
[groaning]
- ♪
♪
- [groans]
- ♪
- [flames crackling]
- [groaning]
- [gasps]
[panting]
- [thunderous
electrical zapping]
- AZULA:
[evil laughter]
- [groaning]
- [electrical zapping]
- KATARA: [groans]
- I'd really rather
our family physician
look after little Zu Zu,
if you don't mind.
- [electrical zapping]
- ♪
- AZULA: Zu Zu,
you don't look so good.
[grunt of effort]
Yah!
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [grunts]
- ♪
- There you are,
filthy peasant.
- ♪
♪
- [bubbles gurgling]
- ♪
- BOTH:
[coughing]
- [grunts]
[grunting]
- [groaning]
- ♪
- [weakly]
Thank you, Katara.
- I think I'm the one
who should be thanking you.
- [hyperventilating]
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[screaming,
sobbing continues]
- ♪
- [gasps]
- [explosion]
- ♪
♪
- [gasps, screams]
- ♪
- AANG: [otherworldly voice]
Firelord Ozai,
you and your forefathers
have devastated
the balance of this world,
and now, you shall pay
the ultimate price.
- [dramatic music]
♪
- [water splashes]
- ♪
- [groaning]
- No. I am not gonna
end it like this.
- Even with all power
in the world,
you are still weak.
- ♪
♪
- MEN: [deep-toned
voices chanting]
- ♪
- LION-TURTLE: In the era
before the Avatar,
we bent not the elements,
but the energy
within ourselves.
- MEN: [deep-toned
chanting continues]
- ♪
♪
- LION-TURTLE: To bend
another's energy,
your own spirit
must be unbendable,
or you will be
corrupted and destroyed.
- ♪
[music soaring]
♪
- BOTH:
[groan]
- ♪
- [weakly grunting]
[groans]
What? What did
you do to me?
- I took away
your Firebending.
You can't use it to hurt or
threaten anyone else ever again.
- ♪
- [inhaling slowly]
[exhaling slowly]
- ♪
♪
- [chattering]
- ♪
- You did it!
You should've seen yourself!
It was amazing!
You were all like...
[imitating zapping,
punching, explosions]
...and the Firelord
was all like...
[imitating groaning,
gasping, choking]
- So, did you,
you know,
finish the job?
- I'm still alive.
- I learned there
was another way
to defeat him
and restore balance.
I took his bending away.
- Wow, who taught
you that?
- A giant lion-turtle.
- You have the craziest
adventures when you disappear.
- Well, look at
you, buster.
Now that your
firebending is gone,
I guess we should call
you the "Loser Lord".
- I am the Phoenix King.
[groaning]
- [heavy thud]
- Oh, sorry, didn't
mean to offend you,
Phoenix King of getting
his butt-whooped.
- Yeah, or how about "King of
the Guys Who Don't Win"?
- Leave the nicknames
to us, honey.
- ♪
♪
- [groaning]
- You need some
help with that?
- Mai. You're okay.
They let you
out of prison?
- My uncle pulled
some strings.
And it doesn't hurt when a new
Firelord is your boyfriend.
- So, does this mean you
don't hate me anymore?
- I think it means
I actually kind of like you.
- ♪
- But don't ever break
up with me again.
- ♪
- [mixed conversations]
- Dad!
- ♪
- I heard what
you two did.
I am the proudest
father in the world.
And your mother
would be proud, too.
- SOKKA: There's
my favorite warriors.
I have to admit, I kinda
missed the face paint.
So, how's it feel to be
back in uniform again?
- It feels great!
- Careful, Suki!
Ty Lee's pretending to be
a Kyoshi Warrior again.
- It's okay.
She's one of us now.
- [gasps]
- Yeah, the girls and I
really bonded in prison
and after a few
chi-blocking lessons,
they said I could
join their group.
We're gonna be
best friends forever.
- ♪
- I can't believe a year
ago my purpose in life
was hunting
you down and now...
- And now we're friends.
- Yeah.
We are friends.
- I can't believe
a year ago I was still
frozen in a block
of ice.
The world's
so different now.
- And it's gonna be
even more different.
We'll rebuild
it together.
- ♪
- [gong ringing]
- CROWD:
[cheering]
- Please,
the real hero...
is the Avatar.
- ♪
- CROWD:
[cheering]
- ♪
- ZUKO: Today, this war
is finally over!
- CROWD:
[cheering]
- I promised my uncle
that I would restore
the honor of
the Fire Nation and I will.
The road ahead of
us is challenging.
A hundred years
of fighting
has left the world
scarred and divided.
But with
the Avatar's help,
we can get it
back on the right path,
and begin a new era
of love and peace.
- ♪
- All hail Firelord Zuko!
- CROWD:
[cheering]
- ♪
♪
- I should count
myself lucky
the new Firelord has
graced me with his presence
in my lowly prison cell.
- You should count
yourself lucky
that the Avatar
spared your life.
- Hmmm...
- Banishing me
was the best thing
you could have done
for my life.
It put me on
the right path.
Perhaps your time in here
can do the same for you.
- Why are you really here?
- Because you're
gonna tell me something.
Where is my mother?
- ♪
- [grunt of effort]
- [laughing]
- APPA:
[bellowing]
- [instrument
playing calming music]
[music stops]
- [music resumes]
- Zuko, stop moving!
I'm trying to
capture the moment.
I wanted to do
a painting
so we'd always remember
the good times together.
- That's very thoughtful
of you, Sokka.
Wait, why did you give
me Momo's ears?
- SOKKA: Those are
your hair loopies.
- At least you don't
look like a porcupine.
My hair is not
that spiky.
- SUKI:
I look like a man.
- TOPH: And why did you
paint me firebending?
- I thought it looked more
exciting that way.
Oh, you think you could do
a better job, Momo?
- MOMO:
[chattering]
- UNCLE IROH: Hey, my belly
is not that big anymore--
I've really trimmed down.
- TOPH: Well, I think
you all look perfect!
- ALL:
[laughing]
♪
[music soaring]