( main theme playing )
( woman vocalizing )
Check the circuit.
All operating, sir.
It can't be
the screen then.
Definitely something
out there, captain.
Headed this way.
TYLER:
Could be these meteroids.
ONE:
No. It's something else.
There's still
something out there.
( alarm beeping )
It's coming
at the speed of light.
Collision course.
The meteorite beam has not
deflected it, captain.
Evasive maneuvers, sir?
Steady as we go.
( alarm stops )
It's a radio wave, sir.
We're passing through
an old-style distress signal.
They were keyed
to cause interference
and attract attention
this way.
A ship in trouble making
a forced landing, sir.
GARISON:
That's it.
No other message.
I have a fix. It comes from
the Talos star group.
We've no ships or
Earth colonies that far out.
Their call letters check
with a survey expedition--
S.S. Columbia.
Disappeared in that region
approximately 18 years ago.
It would take that long
for a radio beam
to travel from there to here.
Records show the Talos group
has never been explored.
Solar system similar to Earth.
Eleven planets.
Number four seems
to be Class M--
oxygen atmosphere.
And they could still be alive,
even after 18 years.
If they survived the crash.
We aren't going to go
to be certain?
Not without any indication
of survivors, no.
We'll continue on
to the Vega Colony
and take care of our own sick
and injured first.
You have the helm.
Maintain present course.
ONE:
Yes, sir.
( beeps )
BOYCE ( over comms ):
Boyce here.
PIKE:
Drop by my cabin, doctor.
( knock on door )
What's that?
I didn't say there was
anything wrong with me.
I understand we picked up
a distress signal.
That's right.
Unless we get anything
more positive on it,
it seems to me the condition
of our own crew
takes precedent.
I'd like to log the ship's
doctor's opinion, too.
Oh, I concur with yours,
definitely.
Good. I'm glad you do.
'Cause we're going to stop
first at the Vega Colony
and replace anybody
who needs hospitalization
and also--
( ice clinks )
What the devil are you
putting in there? Ice?
Who wants
a warm martini?
What makes you think
I need one?
Sometimes a man will
tell his bartender
things he'll never
tell his doctor.
What's been
on your mind, Chris?
The fight
on Rigel VII?
Shouldn't it be?
My only yeoman and
two others dead, seven injured.
Was there anything
you personally
could've done
to prevent it?
Oh, I should have
smelled trouble when I saw
the swords and the armor.
Instead of that,
I let myself get trapped
in that deserted fortress
and attacked by one
of their warriors.
Oh, Chris you set
standards for yourself
no one could meet.
you treat everyone on board
like a human being
except yourself.
And now, you're tired,
and you--
You bet I'm tired.
You bet.
I'm tired of being
responsible for 203 lives.
I'm tired of deciding
which mission is too risky
and which isn't,
and who's going
on the landing party
and who doesn't,
and who lives...
and who dies.
Boy, I've had it, Phil.
To the point of finally
taking my advice,
a rest leave?
To the point
of considering resigning.
And do what?
Well, for one thing,
go home.
Nice little town
with 50 miles
of parkland around it.
Remember I told you
I had two horses?
Used to take some food
and ride out all day.
Ah, that sounds exciting.
Ride out with
a picnic lunch every day.
I said that's one place
I might go.
Or I'd go into
business on Regulus
or on the Orion colony.
You, an Orion trader,
dealing in green animal
women, slaves?
The point is that this
isn't the only life available.
There's a whole galaxy
of things to choose from.
Not for you.
A man either lives life
as it happens to him,
meets it head-on
and licks it, or he...
turns his back on it
and starts
to wither away.
Now you're beginning to talk
like a doctor, bartender.
Take your choice.
We both get the same
two kinds of customers--
the living
and the dying.
( intercom whistles )
Mr. Spock here.
We're intercepting
a follow-up message, sir.
There are crash survivors
on Talos.
GARISON:
"Eleven survivors from crash.
"Gravity and oxygen
within limits.
"Food and water
obtainable.
But unless--"
The message faded
at that point, sir.
Address intercraft.
System open.
This is the captain.
Our destination
is the Talos star group.
Our time warp--
factor seven.
Course computed
and on the screen.
All decks have
acknowledged, sir.
Engage.
( dramatic theme playing )
( woman vocalizing )
On course, sir.
Yeoman.
Yes, sir.
I thought I told you that
when I'm on the bridge--
But you wanted
the reports by 0500.
It's 0500 now, sir.
Oh. I see.
Thank you.
She's replacing
your former yeoman, sir.
She does a good job,
all right.
It's just that
I can't get used
to having
a woman on the bridge.
No offense,
lieutenant.
You're different,
of course.
( mysterious theme playing )
TYLER:
We've settled
into orbit, sir.
Geological lab report
complete, captain.
Preliminary lab
survey ready, sir.
Spectrography?
Our reading shows
an oxygen nitrogen
atmosphere, sir,
heavy with inert elements,
but well within safety limits.
Gravity?
Zero point nine of Earth.
Captain?
Reflections, sir,
from the plane's surface.
As I read it,
they polarize out
as rounded metal bits.
Could be parts
of a spaceship hull.
PIKE:
Prep a landing party of six.
You feel up to it?
Yes, sir.
Sorry, Number One.
With little information on
this planet,
we'll have
to leave the ship's
most experienced
officer here covering us.
Of course, sir.
( ship humming )
There's no indication of
problems down there,
but let's not
take any chances.
Yes, sir. There's a canyon
to the left.
We can set you down there
completely unobserved.
All right.
( beeping )
( transporter chiming )
( chiming stops )
( indistinct humming )
( plant humming )
( humming stops )
( humming resumes )
( plant humming )
Sir.
( mysterious theme playing )
They're men.
They're humans.
PIKE:
Captain Christopher Pike,
United Spaceship Enterprise.
Dr. Theodore Haskins.
American Continent
Institute.
Is Earth all right?
The same old Earth,
and you'll see it very soon.
And you won't believe
how fast you can get back.
The time barrier's
been broken.
Our new ships can--
( mysterious theme playing )
This is Vina.
Her parents are dead.
She was born
almost as we crashed.
( indistinct chattering )
( communicator beeps )
Enterprise.
ONE ( over comms ):
Landing party, come in.
We'll begin transporting
the survivors
and their effects
up to you very shortly.
Quarters are
being prepared, sir.
Have I permission to send out
scouting
and scientific parties now?
That's affirmative on--
You appear to be healthy
and intelligent, captain.
A prime specimen.
ONE:
I didn't get
that last message, captain.
Uh, affirmative
on request.
Landing party out.
You must forgive
her choice of words, captain.
She's lived her whole life
with a collection
of aging scientists.
If they can spare you
a moment,
I'd like to make
my medical report.
I think it's time
to show the captain our secret.
Their health is excellent,
almost too good.
There's a reason
for our condition,
but we've had some doubt
if Earth is ready
to learn the secret.
Let the girl show you.
We'll accept your judgment.
( mysterious theme playing )
You're tired,
but don't worry.
You'll feel
much better soon.
Don't you see it?
Here and here.
I don't understand.
You will.
You're a perfect choice.
( ominous theme playing )
( zaps )
Captain!
( communicator beeps )
Spock here.
ONE ( over comms ):
Landing party, come in.
There is no survivors'
encampment, Number One.
This is all
some sort of trap.
We've lost the captain.
Do you read?
( water dripping steadily )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( knocks )
( pants )
( wall vibrates )
( indistinct snarling )
( growls )
Can you hear me?
My name is
Christopher Pike,
commander of the space
vehicle Enterprise
from a stellar group at the
other end of this galaxy.
Our intentions are peaceful.
Can you understand me?
TALOSIAN:
It appears, magistrate,
that the intelligence
of the specimen
is shockingly limited.
MAGISTRATE:
This is no surprise,
since his vessel
was baited here so easily
with a simulated message.
As you can read
in its thoughts,
it is only now
beginning to suspect
that the survivors
and encampment
were a simple illusion
we placed in their minds.
You're not speaking,
yet I can hear you.
MAGISTRATE:
You will note the confusion
as it reads
our thought transmissions.
All right, then.
Telepathy.
You can read my mind.
I can read yours.
Now, unless you want my ship
to consider capturing me
an unfriendly act--
MAGISTRATE:
You now see the primitive
fear threat reaction.
The specimen is about to boast
of his strength,
the weaponry of his vessel,
and so on.
Next...
frustrated into a need
to display physical prowess,
the creature
will throw himself
against the transparency.
( wall vibrating )
( sighs ):
If you were in here,
wouldn't you test the strength
of these walls, too?
There's a way out of any cage,
and I'll find it.
MAGISTRATE:
Despite its frustration,
the creature
appears more adaptable
than our specimens
from other planets.
We can soon begin the
experiment.
( ominous theme playing )
SPOCK:
The inhabitants
of this planet
must live deep underground.
Probably manufacture food
and other needs down there.
Now, our tests indicate
the planet's surface,
without considerably
more vegetation or some animals,
is simply too barren
to support life.
So we just thought
we saw survivors
there, Mr. Spock.
Exactly. An illusion,
placed in our minds by
this planet's inhabitants.
It was a perfect illusion.
They had us seeing
just what we wanted to see,
human beings who'd survived
with dignity and bravery,
and everything
entirely logical
right down to the building
of the camp,
the tattered clothing,
everything.
( sighs )
Now, let's be sure we understand
the danger of this.
The inhabitants of this planet
can read our minds.
They can create illusions
out of a person's
own thoughts, memories,
and experiences,
even out of
a person's own desires.
Illusions just as real
and solid as this table top,
and just as impossible
to ignore.
Any estimate what they might
want one of us for?
They may simply be
studying the captain
to find how Earth people
are put together.
Or it could be
something more.
TYLER:
Then why aren't we
doing anything?
Now, that entry may have stood
up against hand lasers,
but we can transfer
the ship's power against it--
enough to blast
half a continent.
Look.
Brains three times
the size of ours.
If we start buzzing about
down there,
we're liable to find
their mental power is so great,
they could reach out
and swat this ship
as though it were a fly.
It's Captain Pike
they've got.
He needs help,
and he probably needs it fast.
Engineering deck will rig
to transmit ship's power.
We'll try blasting
through that metal.
( melancholy theme playing )
TALOSIAN:
Thousands of us
are already probing
the creature's thoughts,
magistrate.
We find excellent
memory capacity.
MAGISTRATE:
I read most strongly
a recent death struggle
in which it fought
to protect its life.
We will begin with this,
giving the specimen something
more interesting to protect.
( dramatic theme playing )
VINA:
Come on!
We must hide ourselves.
Come, come.
Hurry!
It's deserted.
There'll be weapons
and perhaps food.
This is Rigel VII.
Please! We must
hide ourselves.
I was in a cage,
a cell in some kind of a zoo.
I must still be there.
Come on!
They've reached into my mind,
and taken the memory of
somewhere I've been.
( roars )
The killer!
( gasps )
It's starting
just as it
happened two weeks ago--
( roars )
Except for you.
Longer hair, different dress,
but it is you.
The one the survivors
called Vina.
( roars )
Or rather,
the image of Vina.
But why you again?
Why didn't they create
a different girl?
( roaring )
Quick! If you attack
while it's not looking...
But it's only a dream.
( roars )
You have to kill him,
as you did here before.
You can tell my jailers
I won't go along with it.
I'm not an animal
performing for its supper.
It doesn't matter
what you call this.
You'll feel it--
that's what matters--
you'll feel every moment
of whatever happens to you.
( clanging )
( roaring )
Please!
Don't you know
what he'll do to us?
( growls )
( dramatic theme swells )
Why would an illusion
be frightened?
Because that's the way
you imagined me.
Who are you?
You act as if
this were real to you, too.
Careful!
( growls )
( screams )
( roaring )
( Vina gasps )
( screaming )
( grunts )
( growls )
( gasps )
It's over.
Why are you here?
To please you.
Are you real?
As real as you wish.
Oh, no.
No, that's not any answer.
I've never met you before,
never even imagined you.
Perhaps they made me
out of dreams
you've forgotten.
And dressed you in
the same metal fabric they wear?
Well I have
to wear something.
Don't I?
Or I can wear
whatever you wish,
or be anything you wish.
So they can see how their
specimen performs?
They want to see how I react.
Is that it?
Don't you have a dream,
something you've always
wanted very badly?
Or do they do more
than just watch me?
Do they...
feel with me, too?
You can have
whatever dream you want.
I can become anything,
any woman
you've ever imagined.
You can have
anything you want
in the whole universe.
Let me...
please you.
Yes, yes,
you can please me.
If you can tell me
about them.
Is there any way
I can keep them
from probing my mind,
from using my thoughts
against me?
Does that frighten you?
Does that mean
there is a way?
You're a fool!
Since you're not real,
there's not much point
in continuing this
conversation, is there?
( mysterious theme playing )
All circuits engaged,
Mr. Spock.
SPOCK ( over comms ):
Standing by, Number One.
( cannon humming )
Take cover.
SPOCK:
Ten... Nine...
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One.
Increase to full power.
Can you give us anymore?
SPOCK:
Our circuits
are beginning to heat.
We'll have to cease power.
Disengage.
( cannon powering down )
The top of that knoll
should have been sheared off
the first second.
Maybe it was.
It's what I tried to explain
in the briefing room.
Their power
of illusion is so great,
we can't be sure
of anything we do...
or anything we see.
Perhaps if you asked me
some questions
I could answer.
How far can they
control my mind?
If I tell you,
then will you pick
some dream you've had
and let me
live it with you?
Perhaps.
They can't actually
make you do
anything you don't want to--
But they try to trick me with
their illusions.
And they can punish you
when you're not cooperative.
You'll find out about that.
Did they ever live
on the surface of this planet?
Why did they go underground?
War,
thousands of centuries ago.
That's why
it's so barren up there?
The planet's only now becoming
able to support life again.
So the Talosians
who came underground
found life limited here
and they concentrated
on developing
their mental power.
But they found
it's a trap,
like a narcotic.
Because when dreams
become more important
than reality,
you give up travel,
building, creating.
You even forget how
to repair the machines
left behind by your ancestors.
You just sit, living
and reliving other lives
left behind
in the thought record.
Or sit probing the minds
of zoo specimens like me.
You're better
than the theater to them.
They create an illusion
for you.
They watch you react,
feel your emotions.
They have a whole collection
of specimens,
descendants of life
brought back long ago
from all over
this part of the galaxy.
Which means they had to have
more than one
of each animal.
Please.
They'll need a pair
of humans too.
Where do they intend to get
the Earth woman?
VINA:
You said if I answered
your questions--
PIKE:
But that was a bargain
with something
that didn't exist.
You said you weren't real,
remember?
I'm a woman,
as real and as human
as you are.
We're like Adam and Eve.
If we--
( gasps )
Don't, please!
( yells ):
Don't punish me!
( screaming )
( mysterious theme playing )
The vial contains
a nourishing protein complex.
Is the keeper
actually communicating
with one of his animals?
If the form and the color
is not appealing,
it can appear as any food you
wish to visualize.
And if I prefer--
To starve?
You overlook the unpleasant
alternative
of punishment.
( groaning )
( screaming )
( dramatic theme swelling )
MAGISTRATE:
From a fable you once heard
in childhood.
You will now consume
the nourishment.
Why not just put irresistible
hunger in my mind?
'Cause you can't,
can you?
You do have limitations,
don't you?
If you continue to disobey,
from deeper in your mind,
there are things
even more unpleasant.
( wall vibrates )
That's very interesting.
Now to the female.
You were startled.
Weren't you
reading my mind then?
As you've conjectured,
an Earth vessel
did crash on our planet,
but with only
a single survivor.
No, let's stay
on the first subject.
All I wanted
for that moment was
to get my hands
around your neck.
We repaired
the survivor's injuries
and found the species
interesting.
Do primitive thoughts put up a
block you can't read through?
It became necessary
to attract a mate.
All right, all right,
let's talk about the girl.
You seem to be going out of
your way to make her attractive,
to make me feel protective.
This is necessary
in order to perpetuate
the species.
It seems
more important to you now
that I begin to accept her
and like her.
We wish our specimens
to be happy
in their new life.
Assuming that's a lie,
why would you want me
attracted to her?
So I'll feel love in a
husband-wife relationship?
That would be necessary
only if you intend
to build a family group
or perhaps a whole
human community.
With the female now
properly conditioned.
You mean properly punished!
I'm the one who's not
cooperating.
Why don't you punish me?
First, an emotion
of protectiveness,
now one of sympathy.
Excellent.
VINA:
You want some coffee, dear?
( birds chirping )
( peaceful theme playing )
I left the thermos
hooked to my saddle.
( whinnies )
Tango!
You old devil, you.
Sorry I don't have
any su--
Well, they think of everything,
don't they?
VINA:
Hey! The coffee.
Is it good to be home?
They read our minds very well.
Home, anything else I want
if I cooperate.
Is that it?
Have you forgotten
my headaches, darling?
I get them when you talk
strangely like this.
Look, I'm sorry
they punish you
but we can't let them--
My, it turned out
to be a lovely day,
didn't it?
It's funny.
Just about 24 hours ago,
I was telling
the ship's doctor
how much I wanted something
not very different
from what we have here.
An escape from reality,
a life with no frustrations,
no responsibilities.
Now that I have it,
I understand
the doctor's answer.
I hope you're hungry.
These little white sandwiches
are your mother's recipe
for chicken tuna.
'Cause you either
live life,
bruises,
skinned knees, and all,
or you turn your back on it
and start dying.
The doctor's going to be
happy about one part, at least--
He said
I needed a rest.
Well, this is
a lovely place to rest.
Yeah, I used to ride through
here when I was a kid.
It's not as pretty as
some of the parkland
around the big cities, but...
That's Mojave.
That's where I was born.
That's supposed to be
news to your wife?
You're home.
You can even stay if you want.
Wouldn't it be nice
showing your children
where you once played?
These headaches, they'll be
hereditary you know.
Would you wish them on a child
or a whole group of children?
It's foolish.
Is it?
Look...
first, they made me
protect you
and then feel
sympathy for you.
And now, we have these
familiar surroundings
and a comfortable
husband-wife relationship.
Well, they don't need
all this for just passion.
What they're after is respect
and mutual dependence.
They say in the olden days,
all this was a desert,
just blowing sand and cactus.
But we're not here,
neither of us!
We're in a menagerie, a cage.
No!
I can't help
either one of us
if you won't
give me a chance.
You told me once
they used illusions
as a narcotic.
They couldn't even
repair the machines
left by their ancestors.
Is that why they want us,
to build a colony of slaves?
Stop it!
Don't you care
what they'll do to us?
Back in my cage,
it seemed for a couple of
minutes
that our keeper
couldn't read my thoughts.
Do emotions like hate--
keeping hate
in your mind--
does that block off
our mind from them?
Yes.
They can't read through
primitive emotions.
But you can't
keep it up for long enough.
I've tried.
They keep at you and at you,
year after year,
tricking and punishing.
And they won.
They own me.
( melancholy theme playing )
I know you must
hate me for that.
Oh, no,
I don't hate you.
I can guess
what it was like.
But that's not enough.
Don't you see?
They read my thoughts,
my feelings,
my dreams of what would be
a perfect man.
And that's why
they picked you.
I can't help
but love you,
and they expect you
to feel the same way.
If they can read
my mind,
then they know
I'm attracted to you.
I was from
the very first moment
I saw you in
the survivor's camp.
TALOSIAN:
A curious species.
They have fantasies they hide
even from themselves.
I'm beginning to see why
none of this
has worked for you.
You've been home
and fighting, as on Rigel.
That's not new
to you either.
A person's strongest dreams
are about what he can't do.
Yes.
A ship's captain--
always having
to be so formal,
so decent and honest
and proper.
You must wonder
what it would be like
to forget all that.
( foreign music playing )
Nice place you have
here, Mr. Pike.
Vina?
ORION:
Glistening green.
Almost like secret dreams
a bored ship captain might have.
Funny how they are
on this planet--
They actually like being
taken advantage of.
Suppose you had all
of space to choose from
and this was only
one small sample?
Wouldn't you say
it was worth a man's soul?
( music stops )
( mysterious theme playing )
Now, we've located
a magnetic field.
Seems to come from
their underground generator.
But could that be
an illusion, too?
Better you all know
the situation.
We're hoping to transport
down inside
the Talosian community.
If our measurements
and readings
are an illusion also,
one could find oneself
materialized inside solid rock.
Nothing will be said
if any volunteer
wants to back out.
( transporter beeps  )
( transporter humming )
The women!
( mysterious theme playing )
Captain!
Captain?
No! Let me finish!
But we were a party of six.
We were the only ones
transported.
It's not fair.
You don't need them.
They don't work.
They were fully charged
when we left.
It's dead.
I can't make a signal.
What is it?
Don't-- don't say anything.
I'm filling my mind
with a picture
of beating their huge,
misshapen heads to pulp!
Thoughts so primitive,
they black out everything else.
I'm filling my mind
with hate!
How long can you
block your thoughts--
A few minutes, an hour?
How can that help?
Leave him alone.
He doesn't need you.
He's already picked me.
Picked her?
For what?
I don't understand.
Now, there's a fine choice
for intelligent offspring.
Offspring?
As in children?
Offspring as in he's Adam.
Is that it?
You're no better choice.
They'd have more luck
crossing him with a computer.
Well, shall we do
a little time computation?
There was a Vina
listed on that expedition
as an adult crewman.
Now, adding 18 years
to your age then--
( chimes )
( no audio )
It's not fair!
I did what you asked!
MAGISTRATE:
Since you resist
the present specimen,
you now have a selection.
I'll break out
of this zoo somehow
and get to you.
Is your blood red like ours?
I'm going to find out.
Each of the two new specimens
has qualities in her favor.
The female you call
Number One
has the superior mind
and would produce highly
intelligent children.
Although she seems
to lack emotion,
this is largely a pretense.
She often has fantasies
involving you.
All I want to do
is get my hands on you.
Can you read
these thoughts--
images of hate, killing?
The other new arrival
has considered you
unreachable,
but now is realizing
this has changed.
The factors in her favor
are youth and strength
plus unusually strong
female drives.
You'll find my thoughts
more interesting,
thoughts so primitive,
you can't understand,
emotions so ugly--
Ugh!
( dramatic theme playing )
MAGISTRATE:
Wrong thinking
is punishable.
Right thinking
will be as quickly rewarded.
You will find it
an effective combination.
( gasping )
Captain.
No.
No. Don't help me.
I have to concentrate.
They can't read
through hate.
Address intercraft.
Open, sir.
This is the acting captain
speaking.
We have no choice now
but to consider
the safety of this vessel
and the remainder of the crew.
We're leaving.
SPOCK:
All decks prepare
for hyperdrive.
Time warp factor--
Mr. Spock, the ship's controls
have gone dead!
Engine room!
GARISON:
Open.
Mr. Spock here. Switch to
rockets we're blasting out.
PITCAIRN ( over comms ):
All systems are out, bridge.
We've got nothing.
There's nothing.
Every system aboard
is fading out!
( mysterious theme playing )
( dramatic theme playing )
( both grunting )
Now, you hold still,
or I'll break your--
Don't hurt him!
They don't mean to be evil.
I've had some samples
of how good they are.
( roars )
You stop this illusion,
or I'll twist
your head off!
All right.
You try one more illusion,
you try anything at all,
and I'll break your neck.
Your ship.
Release me,
or we'll destroy it.
( clattering )
SPOCK:
Nothing.
If not for the batteries,
we'd lose gravitation, oxygen.
( alarm sounds )
TYLER:
The computers!
I can't shut it off!
It's running
through our library--
Tapes, microrecords,
everything.
It doesn't make sense!
Could be
we've waited too long.
It's collecting all the
information stored in this fly.
They've decided to swat us.
He's not bluffing,
captain.
With illusion they can make your
crew work the wrong controls
or push any button
it takes to destroy your ship.
I'm going to gamble
you're too intelligent
to kill for no reason
at all.
On the other hand,
I've got a reason.
I'm willing to bet
you've created an illusion
this laser is empty.
I think it just
blasted a hole in that window,
and you're keeping
us from seeing it.
You want me to test my theory
out on your head?
Captain!
( ominous theme playing )
Make contact, Number One.
They kept us
from seeing this too.
We cut through
and never knew it.
Captain!
As you see,
your attempt to escape
accomplished nothing.
I want to contact
our ship.
You are now on the surface,
where we wished you to be.
With the female
of your choice,
you will now begin
carefully guided lives.
And start
by burying you?
That is your choice.
To help you reclaim
the planet's surface,
our zoological gardens
will furnish
a variety of plant life.
Look,
I'll make a deal with you--
you and your life for the lives
of these two Earth women.
Since our lifespan
is many times yours,
we have time
to evolve you
into a society
trained to serve
as artisans,
technicians--
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
You give me proof that
our ship is all right,
send these two back,
and I'll stay with Vina.
It's wrong to create
a whole race of humans
to live as slaves.
Is this a deception?
Do you intend
to destroy yourselves?
What is that?
The weapon is building up
an overload--
A forced chamber
explosion.
You still have time
to get underground.
Well, go on!
( weapon humming )
And just to show you
how primitive humans
are, Talosian,
you go with her.
If--if you all think
it's this important,
then I can't go, either.
I suppose if they have
one human being,
they might try again.
Wait!
( humming slows )
TALOSIAN:
Their method
of storing records
is crude
and consumed much time.
Are you prepared
to assimilate it?
We had not believed
this possible.
The customs and history
of your race
show a unique hatred
of captivity.
Even when it's pleasant
and benevolent,
you prefer death.
This makes you too violent
and dangerous a species
for our needs.
He means that
they can't use you.
You're free to go
back to the ship.
And that's it?
No apologies?
You captured one of us,
threatened all of us.
Your unsuitability
has condemned the Talosian race
to eventual death.
Is this not sufficient?
No other specimen
has shown your adaptability.
You were our last hope.
But wouldn't some
form of trade,
mutual co-operation...
Your race would learn
our power of illusion
and destroy itself too.
( communicator whistles )
Captain, we have
transporter control now.
Let's get back to the ship.
I can't.
I can't go with you.
PITCAIRN:
Sir, it just came on.
We can't shut the power off.
( communicator whistles )
Mr. Spock here.
TYLER ( over comms ):
All power has come on,
Mr. Spock.
The helm is answering to
control.
( transporter humming )
The captain?
( dramatic theme playing )
You see why
I can't go with you?
This is the female's
true appearance.
They found me
in the wreckage
dying,
a lump of flesh.
They rebuilt me.
Everything works,
but they had
never seen a human.
They had no guide
for putting me back together.
It was necessary
to convince you
her desire to stay
is an honest one.
You'll give her back
her illusion of beauty?
And more.
( melancholy theme playing )
She has an illusion,
and you have reality.
May you find your way
as pleasant.
PITCAIRN:
Mr. Spock, the system is
coming on again.
( transporter humming )
What's happened to Vina?
Isn't she coming with us?
No.
No, and I agreed
with her reasons.
Hold on a minute.
Oh, I feel fine.
Just fine.
Yeah. You look
100 percent better.
You recommended a rest
and change of pace, didn't you?
Mm-hmm.
I've even been home.
Does that make you happy?
Yeoman.
Yes, sir.
I told you that when
I'm on the bridge, I--
Oh.
Oh, yes, the--
the reports.
Thank you.
Sir,
I was wondering,
just curious.
Who would have been Eve?
Yeoman!
You've delivered your report.
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, sir.
Eve, sir?
Eve as in Adam?
As in all ship's doctors
are dirty old men.
What are we running here,
a cadet ship, Number One?
Are we ready or not?
All decks show ready, sir.
Engage.
( dramatic theme playing )
( woman vocalizing )