[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 1513.1.
OUR POSITION,
ORBITING PLANET M-113.
ON BOARD THE ENTERPRISE,
MR. SPOCK,
TEMPORARILY IN COMMAND.
ON THE PLANET,
THE RUINS OF AN ANCIENT
AND LONG DEAD CIVILIZATION.
SHIP SURGEON McCOY AND MYSELF
ARE NOW BEAMING DOWN
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
OUR MISSION,
ROUTINE MEDICAL EXAMINATION
OF ARCHEOLOGIST ROBERT CRATER
AND HIS WIFE, NANCY.
ROUTINE BUT FOR THE FACT
THAT NANCY CRATER
IS THAT ONE WOMAN
IN DR. McCOY'S PAST.
SHALL WE PICK SOME FLOWERS,
DOCTOR?
WHEN A MAN VISITS
AN OLD GIRLFRIEND,
SHE USUALLY EXPECTS
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
IS THAT HOW YOU GET GIRLS
TO LIKE YOU, BY BRIBING THEM?
DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
ANYONE AROUND, DOES THERE?
THEY'LL BE ALONG.
YOU RUSHED US DOWN
10 MINUTES EARLY.
PROFESSOR CRATER?
PROFESSOR?
MRS. CRATER?
[ BEEPING ]
NERVOUS DR. MCCOY?
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT, I GUESS.
YOU SEE, WE WALKED
OUT OF EACH OTHER'S LIVES
10 YEARS AGO.
SHE MARRIED CRATER,
AND FOR ALL I KNOW,
SHE MAY HAVE FORGOTTEN ME
COMPLETELY.
OH.
OF ALL THE BONEHEAD IDEAS, JIM,
HOW'D I LET MYSELF INTO THINGS
LIKE THIS?
[ SINGING ]
LEONARD.
NANCY.
HELLO.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
LET ME LOOK AT YOU.
YOU HAVEN'T AGED A DAY.
OH, THIS IS CAPTAIN JIM KIRK
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
MRS. CRATER.
I'VE HEARD A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT YOU.
ALL GOOD, I HOPE.
AND CREWMAN DARNELL.
HOW DO YOU DO, MA'AM?
SOMETHING WRONG, DARNELL?
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
BUT MA'AM,
IF I DIDN'T KNOW BETTER,
I WOULD SWEAR
THAT YOU WERE SOMEBODY
I LEFT BEHIND
ON WRIGLEY'S PLEASURE PLANET.
IT'S FUNNY, YOU'RE EXACTLY
LIKE A GIRL THAT--
A LITTLE LESS MOUTH, DARNELL.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO--I MEAN,
I KNOW IT'S IMPOSSIBLE,
OF COURSE.
WHY DON'T YOU STEP OUTSIDE,
DARNELL?
YES, SIR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
MAYBE I'LL STEP OUTSIDE, TOO.
WHAT?
AND LET PLUM EXAMINE ME
ALL ALONE?
PLUM?
PLUM.
A NICKNAME I GAVE LEONARD
WHEN WE WERE VERY YOUNG.
I'LL WAIT FOR THE PROFESSOR,
AND I'LL CATCH YOU BOTH AT ONCE.
I BETTER GO GET BOB.
EVERY TIME HE STARTS DIGGING,
HE FORGETS TIME, SLEEP, FOOD,
EVERYTHING.
BE BACK IN A MINUTE.
IT'S QUITE WARM HERE,
ISN'T IT?
[ MUSIC ]
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION,
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
ADDITIONAL ENTRY.
SINCE OUR MISSION WAS ROUTINE,
WE HAD BEAMED DOWN TO THE PLANET
WITHOUT SUSPICION.
WE WERE TOTALLY UNAWARE
THAT EACH MEMBER
OF THE LANDING PARTY
WAS SEEING A DIFFERENT WOMAN,
A DIFFERENT NANCY CRATER.
PROFESSOR CRATER,
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
THIS IS--
THE HEROIC CAPTAIN
AND THE INTREPID DOCTOR
CROSS INTERSTELLAR SPACE
TO PRESERVE OUR HEALTH.
OH, YOUR SENSE OF DUTY
IS OVERWHELMING.
NOW, WILL YOU PLEASE GO BACK
WHERE YOU CAME FROM
AND TELL WHOEVER ISSUES
YOUR ORDERS
TO LEAVE ME
AND MY WIFE ALONE.
WE NEED ADDITIONAL SALT
AGAINST THE HEAT.
ASIDE FROM THAT, WE'RE DOING
VERY WELL, THANK YOU.
I'M PLEASED TO HEAR
YOU'RE DOING WELL,
BUT I'M REQUIRED TO CONFIRM
THAT FACT.
DOUBTLESS,
THE GOOD SURGEON WILL ENJOY
PRODDING AND POKING US
WITH HIS ARCANE MACHINERY.
GO AWAY.
WE DON'T WANT YOU.
WHAT YOU WANT IS UNIMPORTANT
RIGHT NOW.
WHAT YOU WILL GET
IS WHAT IS REQUIRED BY THE BOOK.
QUOTE.
ALL RESEARCH PERSONNEL
ON ALIEN PLANETS ARE REQUIRED
TO HAVE THEIR HEALTH CERTIFIED
BY A STARSHIP SURGEON
AT ONE YEAR INTERVALS.
LIKE IT OR NOT, PROFESSOR,
AS COMMANDER OF THE STARSHIP,
I'M REQUIRED--
TO SHOW YOUR GOLD BRAID
TO EVERYONE.
YOU LOVE IT, DON'T YOU?
HE'S ALL YOURS, PLUM--DR. McCOY.
SIT DOWN AND BREATH DEEPLY,
PLEASE.
DID I HEAR YOU CALL HIM
DR. McCOY?
YOU DID.
McCOY.
I'VE HEARD NANCY SPEAK
OF A DR. McCOY.
THAT'S ME.
DIDN'T SHE MENTION I WAS HERE?
YOU--YOU'VE SEEN NANCY?
SHE WENT OUT TO GET YOU.
YOU'VE SEEN HER, TOO.
YOU WERE WITH THE GOOD DOCTOR?
YES, WHY?
IT'S JUST THAT IT GIVES ME
GREAT PLEASURE TO KNOW
THAT SHE'S GOTTEN TO SEE
AN OLD FRIEND
AND HAS A CHANCE
FOR SOME COMPANY.
IT'S DIFFERENT FOR ME.
I ENJOY SOLITUDE.
BUT FOR A WOMAN,
YOU UNDERSTAND, OF COURSE.
WELL, IT CERTAINLY
HASN'T AGED HER.
SHE LOOKS EXACTLY AS I KNEW HER
12 YEARS AGO.
AMAZING, JIM,
LIKE A GIRL OF 25.
SORRY. I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
SIT DOWN.
I SEEM TO HAVE FORGOTTEN
MY MANNERS.
QUITE ALL RIGHT.
I'M NOT JOKING, JIM.
SHE HASN'T AGED A DAY.
THERE'S NOT A GRAY HAIR
ON HER HEAD.
SHE'S GOT SOME GRAY, BONES.
EXCUSE ME, PROFESSOR.
SHE'S A HANDSOME WOMAN, YES,
BUT HARDLY 25.
YOU'VE SEEN MY WIFE
WITH THE EYES
OF YOUR PAST ATTACHMENT, DOCTOR.
I'M SURE WHEN NANCY LETS--
WHEN YOU SEE HER AGAIN,
SHE'LL BE OF A BELIEVABLE AGE.
WELL, AT ANY RATE,
SHE DOESN'T LOOK A DAY OVER 30.
GENUINE AFFECTION.
I'M GLAD YOU STILL FEEL IT
FOR HER.
LEONARD, ISN'T IT?
SHE'S A FINE WOMAN.
OPEN YOUR MOUTH.
WHY, I THOUGHT THE MACHINE WAS--
THE MACHINE IS CAPABLE
OF ALMOST ANYTHING.
BUT I'LL STILL PUT MY TRUST
IN A HEALTHY SET OF TONSILS.
NOW, OPEN YOUR MOUTH.
[ SCREAMING ]
[ MUSIC ]
McCOY.
DEAD, JIM.
STRANGE.
RED MOTTLING
ALL OVER HIS FACE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE HAPPENED,
CAPTAIN?
YOU BEAMED DOWN A CREWMAN
WHO DOESN'T KNOW BETTER
THAN TO EAT AN UNTESTED PLANT.
I'VE JUST LOST A CREWMAN,
MRS. CRATER.
I WANNA KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
WELL, I--
TAKE IT EASY, NANCY.
JUST TELL US WHAT YOU KNOW.
WELL, I WAS JUST--
I COULDN'T FIND BOB,
AND I WAS COMING BACK.
I CROSSED TO YOUR CREWMAN.
I WANTED HIM TO KNOW
I WASN'T OFFENDED
BY THE THINGS HE'D SAID
BACK THERE.
YOU REMEMBER.
THEN I NOTICED HE HAD
A BORGIA PLANT IN HIS HAND.
BEFORE I COULD SAY ANYTHING,
HE'D TAKEN A BITE FROM IT.
HE FELL--
LEONARD, YOU'RE LOOKING AT ME
LIKE YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME?
NO. NO, NO, NO.
IT'S NOT THAT AT ALL.
IT'S SOMETHING ENTIRELY
DIFFERENT.
JIM, I SUPPOSE WE COULD COMPLETE
THESE EXAMINATIONS LATER.
WE DON'T NEED AN EXAMINATION.
YOU CAN SEE THAT.
PERHAPS YOU'D BETTER
TAKE YOUR MAN AND--
WE'RE WELL AWARE
OF OUR NEXT DUTIES, PROFESSOR.
WE'LL COMPLETE YOUR EXAMINATIONS
TOMORROW.
[ BEEPING ]
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
Transporter room, Captain.
LOCK ONTO US.
THREE BEAMING UP.
Locked onto you, Captain.
SALT. YOU DID ASK HIM
ABOUT MORE SALT TABLETS?
I'LL TAKE CARE
OF THE PROVISIONING, NANCY.
[ MUSIC ]
MISS UHURA,
YOUR LAST SUB-SPACE LOG
CONTAINED AN ERROR
IN THE FREQUENCIES COLUMN.
MR. SPOCK,
SOMETIMES I THINK IF I HEAR
THAT WORD FREQUENCY ONCE MORE,
I'LL CRY.
CRY?
I WAS JUST TRYING TO START
A CONVERSATION.
WELL, SINCE IT IS ILLOGICAL
FOR A COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER
TO RESENT THE WORD FREQUENCY,
I HAVE NO ANSWER.
NO, YOU HAVE AN ANSWER.
I'M AN ILLOGICAL WOMAN
WHO'S BEGINNING TO FEEL
TOO MUCH A PART
OF THAT COMMUNICATIONS CONSOLE.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL ME
I'M AN ATTRACTIVE YOUNG LADY
OR ASK ME
IF I'VE EVER BEEN IN LOVE?
TELL ME HOW YOUR PLANET, VULCAN,
LOOKS ON A LAZY EVENING
WHEN THE MOON IS FULL.
VULCAN HAS NO MOON, MS. UHURA.
I'M NOT SURPRISED, MR. SPOCK.
[ WHISTLING ]
Transporter room to bridge.
Landing party returning.
They report one death.
BRIDGE ACKNOWLEDGING.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
EXPLAIN.
YOU EXPLAIN.
THAT MEANS
THAT SOMEBODY IS DEAD,
AND YOU JUST SIT THERE.
IT COULD BE CAPTAIN KIRK.
HE'S THE CLOSEST THING YOU HAVE
TO A FRIEND.
LIEUTENANT,
MY DEMONSTRATION OF CONCERN
WILL NOT CHANGE
WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
IS VERY WELL MANNED,
AND THEY WILL CALL ME
IF THEY NEED MY ASSISTANCE.
-SHE CALLED IT A BORGIA PLANT.
-SOMETHING NEW TO ME.
[ WHISTLING ]
Bridge to dispensary.
GO AHEAD, MR. SPOCK.
BORGIA PLANT LISTED
IN LIBRARY RECORD TAPES
AS CARBON GROUP THREE
VEGETATION,
SIMILAR TO EARTH
NIGHTSHADE FAMILY.
ALKALOID POISON.
CHEMICAL STRUCTURE
COMMON TO MOST CLASS M PLANETS.
ABOUT THE STRANGE MOTTLING
ON HIS FACIAL SKIN SURFACE,
THERE IS NO REFERENCE
TO THIS SYMPTOM.
HMM. WELL, THEN THIS MAN
WASN'T POISONED.
STAND BY, MR. SPOCK.
SHE SAID SHE SAW HIM EAT
THE PLANT.
SHE'S MISTAKEN.
I KNOW ALKALOID POISON
AND WHAT TO LOOK FOR.
THERE'S NOT A TRACE OF IT
IN HIS BODY.
THERE WERE BITS OF THE PLANT
IN HIS MOUTH.
JIM, DON'T TELL ME MY BUSINESS.
HE COULD NOT HAVE SWALLOWED ANY.
MY INSTRUMENTS WOULD'VE PICKED
UP ANY TRACE OF IT WHATSOEVER.
THEN WHAT KILLS A HEALTHY MAN--
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING ELSE.
THIS MAN SHOULDN'T BE DEAD.
I CAN'T FIND ANYTHING WRONG
WITH HIM.
ACCORDING TO ALL THE TESTS,
HE SHOULD JUST GET UP
AND JUST WALK AWAY FROM HERE.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'LL HAVE THE TESTS
DOUBLE-CHECKED.
MY EYES MAY BE TRICKING ME.
BUT I SWEAR, JIM,
WHEN I FIRST SAW HER,
SHE LOOKED JUST AS I'D KNOWN HER
10 YEARS AGO.
GRANTED THE MOMENT
I MAY HAVE BEEN LOOKING AT HER
THROUGH A ROMANTIC HAZE.
HOW YOUR LOST LOVE AFFECTS
YOUR VISION, DOCTOR,
DOESN'T INTEREST ME.
I'VE LOST A MAN.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT KILLED HIM.
YES, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 1513.4.
IN ORBIT AROUND PLANET M-113.
ONE CREWMAN,
MEMBER OF THE LANDING PARTY,
DEAD BY VIOLENCE.
CAUSE UNKNOWN.
WE ARE CERTAIN
THE CAUSE OF DEATH
WAS NOT POISON.
MESSAGE, CAPTAIN.
STARSHIP BASED ON CURRENT FOUR
REQUESTING EXPLANATION
OF OUR DELAY HERE, SIR.
SPACE COMMANDER DOMINGUEZ SAYS
WE HAVE SUPPLIES
HE URGENTLY NEEDS.
TELL JOSE HE'LL GET
HIS CHILI PEPPERS
WHEN WE GET THERE.
TELL HIM
THEY'RE PRIME MEXICAN REDS.
I HAND-PICKED THEM MYSELF.
BUT HE WON'T DIE IF HE GOES
A FEW MORE DAYS WITHOUT THEM.
GOT IT?
GOT IT, CAPTAIN.
WELL?
NO MISTAKE IN OUR RECORD TAPES.
BORGIA PLANT,
SOLE DEADLY PROPERTY
IS ALKALOID POISON.
AND PROFESSOR CRATER AND WIFE?
CHECKED OUT PERFECTLY.
THEY ARRIVED HERE
NEARLY FIVE YEARS AGO,
VISITED BY VARIOUS VESSELS,
MADE FAIRLY HEAVY SHIPMENTS
OUT OF ARTIFACTS AND REPORTS.
HOWEVER,
THERE HAS BEEN A MARKED DROP
IN SHIPMENTS
DURING THE LAST YEAR.
[ WHISTLING ]
Dispensary to Captain.
KIRK HERE.
We found something.
WHAT IS IT?
I'd rather not put it
on the speaker.
[ MUSIC ]
FASCINATING.
SO IMPROBABLE,
WE ALMOST DIDN'T CHECK IT.
WHAT?
SODIUM CHLORIDE.
NOT A TRACE OF IT.
THIS MAN HAS NO SALT
IN HIS BODY AT ALL.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN THAT, DOCTOR?
I CAN'T,
EXCEPT WHAT WE NORMALLY CARRY
IN OUR BODIES IS GONE FROM HIS.
HE WOULD DIE ALMOST INSTANTLY.
HOW?
THERE'S NO MARK ON HIS BODY.
EXCEPT THE RED RINGS
ON HIS FACE.
YOU CALLED THAT SKIN MOTTLING.
I THOUGHT IT WAS, SIR.
ANOTHER ERROR ON MY PART.
I'M NOT COUNTING THEM, BONES.
ARE YOU IN THE MOOD
FOR AN APOLOGY?
OH, FORGET IT.
I PROBABLY WAS MOONING OVER HER.
I SHOULD'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT MY JOB.
PERHAPS YOU WERE.
BOTH NANCY AND CRATER
WENT OUT OF THEIR WAY
TO MENTION ONE ITEM THEY NEEDED.
SALT TABLETS.
MR. SPOCK,
OUTFIT A LANDING PARTY.
WE'RE BEAMING DOWN
WITH SOME QUESTIONS.
[ MUSIC ]
ONE MIGHT THINK THAT YOU HAD
MORE IMPORTANT DUTIES
THAN HARASSING PEOPLE, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE.
PROFESSOR, BELIEVE ME, I HAVE.
WHERE IS MRS. CRATER?
I WANNA TALK TO HER, TOO.
CAPTAIN, YOU CAN'T JUST
BEAM DOWN HERE
AND BULLY US
AND INTERFERE WITH OUR WORK.
MRS. CRATER,
I WON'T ASK AGAIN.
POSSIBLY AT THE OTHER DIGGINGS.
WE DON'T KEEP MILITARY LOGS.
GREEN, FIND HER.
YES, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
MR. SPOCK.
Standing by.
STURGEON, TRANSPORT A SAMPLE
OF THE PLANT TO MR. SPOCK.
WE'LL CHECK IF IT'S ACTUALLY
THE BORGIA PLANT
OR SOMETHING
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU GOT THAT, MR. SPOCK?
Complete analysis.
CAPTAIN, CONSIDERING
THE INESCAPABLE FACTS
THAT YOU ARE A TRESPASSER
ON MY PLANET--
YOUR COMPLAINT IS NOTED, SIR.
LOOK, SOMETHING WE DON'T
UNDERSTAND KILLED ONE OF MY MEN.
IT COULD PROVE TO BE A DANGER
TO YOU AND MRS. CRATER, TOO.
WE'VE BEEN HERE
FOR ALMOST FIVE YEARS.
IF THERE WERE ANYTHING
HOSTILE HERE,
WE WOULD KNOW ABOUT IT,
WOULDN'T WE?
BONES, TELL THE PROFESSOR
WHAT THE AUTOPSY REVEALED.
OUR CREWMAN DIED
OF SALT DEPLETION.
SUDDEN TOTAL LOSS OF IT.
MEDICALLY IMPOSSIBLE
BY ANY STANDARDS.
AND BY COINCIDENCE,
BOTH YOU AND MRS. CRATER
REQUESTED SALT TABLETS.
AND YOUR ESTEEMED PHYSICIAN
CANNOT EXPLAIN OUR NEED
FOR SALT TABLETS?
WE'RE ALL AWARE OF THE NEED
FOR SALT
ON A HOT AND ARID PLANET
LIKE THIS, PROFESSOR.
BUT IT'S A MYSTERY,
AND I DON'T LIKE MYSTERIES.
THEY GIVE ME A BELLYACHE,
AND I GOT A BEAUTY RIGHT NOW.
NANCY AND I STARTED
WITH 25 POUNDS.
THIS IS WHAT WE HAVE LEFT.
NOW WHAT IS SO MYSTERIOUS
ABOUT THAT?
SALT.
ONE OF THE MISSIONS
OF THE ENTERPRISE
IS TO PROTECT HUMAN LIFE
IN PLACES LIKE THIS.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO ASK YOU
AND MRS. CRATER
TO STAY ABOARD MY SHIP
UNTIL WE FIND OUT
WHAT KILLED THAT CREWMAN.
-BUT YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
-BUT I CAN, PROFESSOR.
YOU MUSTN'T DO IT.
IT'LL INTERFERE WITH OUR WORK.
HOW?
YOU'VE BEEN HERE FIVE YEARS.
WILL A COUPLE OF DAYS
MAKE A DIFFERENCE?
[ BEEPING ]
MR. SPOCK?
Spock here.
ARRANGE QUARTERS
FOR PROFESSOR AND MRS. CRATER.
DID YOU GET THE PLANT ANALYSIS?
It is the Borgia variety,
Captain.
Could not have caused
Darnell's death.
JIM, HE'S RUN OFF.
NANCY.
YOU, SALT.
I'VE GOT SALT.
SMELL IT.
NANCY.
PROFESSOR CRATER!
PROFESSOR!
JIM.
IT'S STURGEON.
HE'S DEAD.
WE BETTER LOCATE CREWMAN GREEN.
GREEN! GREEN.
CREWMAN GREEN, REPORT.
GREEN.
GREEN!
GREEN! WHERE ARE YOU?
COULD IT BE CRATER?
HE CAME THIS WAY.
I DON'T KNOW.
GREEN!
-DID YOU SEE THIS?
-YES, SIR.
STURGEON WAS DEAD
WHEN I FOUND HIM.
I WAS CIRCLING TO FIND
WHATEVER IT WAS.
SAME RED RINGS ON HIS FACE.
HAVE YOU SEEN NANCY,
MRS. CRATER?
NO, SIR.
I CHECKED ALL THROUGH THE RUINS.
I'M WORRIED ABOUT HER, JIM.
SHE'S NOT AT THE QUARTERS.
SHE'S NOT AT THE DIGGING.
SHE COULD BE IN TROUBLE.
-NANCY!
-CRATER.
NANCY, IT'S LEONARD.
I'M BEAMING ABOARD THE SHIP,
DOCTOR.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE HER.
WE CAN'T SEARCH
THIS WHOLE PLANET ON FOOT.
JIM!
YOU COULD LEARN SOMETHING
FROM MR. SPOCK, DOCTOR.
AND STOP THINKING
WITH YOUR GLANDS.
WITH THE EQUIPMENT
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE
THAT COULD PINPOINT A MATCH
THAT ANYWHERE ON THIS PLANET
OR THE HEAT OF A BODY.
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
KIRK SPEAKING.
THREE TO BEAM UP.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
-KIRK TO BRIDGE.
-Spock here.
BREAK OUT
THE SURFACE SEARCH EQUIPMENT.
I WANT COORDINATES
ON TWO PEOPLE.
Acknowledged.
THERE'S A BODY DOWN HERE,
STURGEON.
WE'LL BRING HIM HOME, SIR.
YOU COULD USE SOME SLEEP, BONES.
ALL RIGHT, JIM.
BRIDGE.
OH, GREEN.
WHAT WENT ON DOWN THERE?
WHO DO YOU THINK YOU ARE?
SOMETHING ODD, CAPTAIN.
YOU SAID TWO PEOPLE.
PROFESSOR AND NANCY CRATER.
I GET A READING
ON ONLY ONE PERSON,
PROBABLY CRATER.
HE'S CIRCLING
AS IF SEARCHING FOR SOMETHING.
EXPAND SEARCH RADIUS.
YES, SIR.
WHY DON'T YOU GO CHASE
AN ASTEROID?
HEY, JANICE, IS THAT FOR ME?
DON'T YOU WISH IT WAS?
HOW ABOUT THAT?
YEAH, HOW'D YOU LIKE TO HAVE HER
AS YOUR OWN PERSONAL YEOMAN?
WHERE ARE YOU, SULU?
IN HERE FEEDING THE WEEPERS,
JANICE.
WELL, I'VE GOT YOUR TRAY.
MAY THE GREAT BIRD OF THE GALAXY
BLESS YOUR PLANET.
THANK YOU.
HELLO BEAUREGARD.
HOW ARE YOU TODAY, DARLING?
HER NAME'S GERTRUDE.
NO. IT'S A HE-PLANT.
A GIRL CAN TELL.
WHY DO PEOPLE HAVE TO CALL
INANIMATE OBJECTS SHE?
LIKE, SHE'S A BAD SHIP.
HE IS NOT AN INANIMATE OBJECT.
HE'S SO ANIMATE,
HE MAKES ME NERVOUS.
IN FACT, I KEEP EXPECTING
ONE OF THESE PLANTS OF YOURS
TO GRAB ME.
HELLO, GREEN.
HE'S NOT TALKING TODAY.
YOU'VE BEEN NIPPING
SAURIAN BRANDY OR SOMETHING?
[ PLANT SCREECHING ]
TAKE IT EASY.
CALM DOWN.
VERY SENSITIVE.
HE'S THE REAL SPOOK.
SUPPOSE HE'S GOING SPACE HAPPY
OR SOMETHING?
THE DOOR TO MY QUARTERS
STILL RATTLES WHEN IT OPENS.
WOULD YOU STOP BY
AND SEE IF YOU CAN DO SOMETHING
ABOUT IT?
THANKS, BOBBY.
CREWMAN, DO I KNOW YOU?
IN A WAY, MA'AM.
YOU WERE JUST THINKING
OF SOMEONE LIKE ME.
I'M GUESSING, OF COURSE,
BUT YOU DO LOOK A LITTLE LONELY.
I SEE.
SO NATURALLY WHEN I'M LONELY,
I THINK OF YOU.
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
SWAHILI?
[ WHISTLING ]
Lt. Uhura to the bridge.
I BETTER GET THIS TRAY BACK.
BYE, BEAUREGARD.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'LL WALK ALONG.
[ WHISTLING ]
Lt. Uhura, report to the bridge.
LT. UHURA,
ON MY WAY, SIR.
McCOY TO BRIDGE,
CAPTAIN THERE?
Kirk here.
Nothing to report, Doctor.
WE HAVEN'T LOCATED MRS. CRATER.
What's the matter,
can't you sleep?
NOPE.
TRY TAKING ONE OF THOSE
RED PILLS YOU GAVE ME LAST WEEK.
YOU'LL SLEEP.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
THE SIMPLE FACT
IS UNLESS THERE'S SOMETHING
SERIOUSLY WRONG
WITH THE SHIP'S EQUIPMENT,
THERE'S ONLY ONE PERSON
WITHIN A 100 MILE CIRCLE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL TRIANGULATE ON THEM.
WE'LL LET PROFESSOR CRATER
EXPLAIN WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIS WIFE.
REMEMBER MY INSTRUCTIONS,
LIEUTENANT.
KEEP A TIGHT FIX ON US.
IF WE LET OUT A YELL,
I WANT AN ARMED PARTY DOWN THERE
BEFORE THE ECHO DIES.
YES, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]
NANCY.
WELL, COME IN,
COME IN.
I'VE BEEN WORRIED SICK
ABOUT YOU.
I WONDER WHY JIM DIDN'T TELL ME
HE FOUND YOU.
I'M SO HAPPY TO SEE YOU,
LEONARD.
THE OTHERS,
THEY--I DON'T RELATE TO THEM
AS MUCH AS WITH YOU.
YOU HAVE SUCH STRONG MEMORIES
OF ME.
WELL, I--
YOU DO CARE,
DON'T YOU, LEONARD?
IT MAKES ME FEEL SO--SO SAFE.
NANCY--
MY HUSBAND?
I LIKE YOUR FEELINGS BETTER.
MUCH STRONGER.
BUT YOU'RE TIRED.
YOU NEED TO REST.
YOU'RE AS BAD AS JIM KIRK.
HE'S BEEN TELLING ME
TO TAKE THESE.
WELL, I THINK YOU SHOULD.
I'LL GET YOU SOME WATER.
[ GASPING ]
LOOK AT HIS FACE.
BRIDGE, SULU.
TROUBLE ON DECK NINE,
SECTION TWO.
WE NEED A MEDICAL TEAM.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STAR DATE, 1513.8.
I AM NOW CERTAIN
THAT THE VIOLENT DEATH
OF MY CREWMEN WAS CAUSED
BY SOME STRANGE LIFE FORM.
I WAS SO WORRIED.
YOUR HUSBAND ACTING STRANGE,
CREWMEN DYING.
YOU'RE SO TIRED, DARLING.
JUST REST NOW.
[ WHISTLING ]
Medical department alert.
Doctors and medics acknowledge.
IT'S NOTHING, DEAR.
IT'S NOTHING.
YOU JUST SLEEP.
NANCY WILL TAKE CARE
OF EVERYTHING.
[ WHISTLING ]
Dr. McCoy to the bridge.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
ADDITIONAL.
ARMED AND ABLE-BODIED CREWMEN
ARE NOT ATTACKED
AND SLAUGHTERED THIS EASILY.
APPARENTLY, THE KILLER
CAN IMMOBILIZE THEM
AS IT APPROACHES
PERHAPS WITH SOME HYPNOTIC
OR PARALYZING POWER.
THE ANSWER LIES
WITH PROFESSOR CRATER.
PROFESSOR CRATER.
GO AWAY.
WE DON'T WANT YOU HERE.
WE--WHERE'S YOUR WIFE,
PROFESSOR?
WE'RE CONCERNED ABOUT HER.
I'M ARMED.
GO AWAY.
WHERE'S YOUR WIFE,
PROFESSOR?
SHE'S NO CONCERN OF YOURS.
WE'RE WORRIED ABOUT HER SAFETY,
AREN'T YOU?
PROFESSOR,
YOU'RE A REASONABLE MAN,
LET ME--
[ BEEPING ]
-KIRK HERE.
-Casualty, Captain.
Barnhart was found dead
on deck nine, same symptoms.
SPOCK CUTTING IN, CAPTAIN.
Something here,
through the arches to your left.
STAND BY, MR. SULU.
SPOCK HAS SOMETHING.
GREEN.
HE BEAMED UP TO THE SHIP
WITH US.
OR SOMETHING DID.
[ BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE FROM KIRK.
Bridge, Sulu.
YOU HAVE AN INTRUDER ABOARD.
COULD BE MASQUERADING
AS CREWMAN GREEN.
GENERAL QUARTERS,
SECURITY CONDITION THREE.
GQ security three, sir.
[ SIREN WAILING ]
General quarter three,
intruder alert.
GQ three,
General quarters three,
intruder alert.
GQ three,
Reporting GQ three secure,
Captain.
Do you require assistance there?
CRATER KNOWS THE CREATURE.
IF WE CAN TAKE HIM ALIVE.
NEGATIVE, LIEUTENANT.
BUT KEEP LOCKED IN ON US.
KIRK OUT.
LET'S GET HIM.
[ EXPLOSION ]
WE DON'T WANT YOU HERE.
WE'RE HAPPY ALONE.
I'LL KILL TO STAY ALONE.
YOU HEAR THAT, KIRK?
OR YOU'LL HAVE TO KILL ME.
I DON'T CARE EITHER WAY.
OBVIOUSLY, TAKING HIM ALIVE
IS GONNA BE DIFFICULT.
SET YOUR PHASER ON ONE-QUARTER.
I'LL LEAVE MINE ON STUN.
AND RISK YOUR LIFE FOR HIS?
HE'S NOT TRYING TO KILL US.
HE'S TRYING TO FRIGHTEN US,
AND HE'S DOING
A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
GQ 3 NOW SECURED
EXCEPT FOR DECKS 5, 7, AND 10.
COME IN, PLEASE.
HE'S NOT IN SUPPLY
AND MAINTENANCE.
ALL RIGHT, UHURA.
ENGINEERING DECK NOW.
RUN THROUGH FIVE PHOTOS
OF THE CREWMAN THERE.
CHECK.
Deck five reporting.
Crewman Green is not
in his quarters.
No one has seen him.
KEEP IN MIND IF YOU FIND HIM,
HE'S NOT CREWMAN GREEN.
CAPTAIN REPORTS GREEN'S DEAD.
AND HE--RATHER IT FOLLOWED ME.
I THOUGHT THERE WAS SOMETHING
TWITCHY ABOUT HIM.
HE--OR WHATEVER--WAS PROBABLY
YOUR CREWMAN, TOO, LIEUTENANT.
HE MUST HAVE BEEN IT.
YOU KNOW, I WOULD HAVE
REMEMBERED A CREWMAN LIKE HIM.
THE CREATURE LEADING
YOU A MERRY CHASE, MR. SULU?
CREATURE?
OR WHATEVER IT IS
THAT'S KILLING THE CREWMEN,
PERHAPS I CAN HELP.
FILL ME IN.
[ BEEPING ]
SENT.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
CRATER?
YOUR WIFE, PROFESSOR,
WHERE IS SHE?
SHE WAS THE LAST OF HER KIND.
THE LAST OF HER KIND?
THE LAST OF ITS KIND.
EARTH HISTORY, REMEMBER?
LIKE THE PASSENGER PIGEON
OR BUFFALO.
OOH, I FEEL STRANGE.
JUST STUNNED.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO THINK
IN A MINUTE.
THE EARTH BUFFALO,
WHAT ABOUT IT?
ONCE THERE WERE MILLIONS
OF THEM,
PRAIRIES BLACK WITH THEM.
ONE HERD COVERED
THREE WHOLE STATES,
AND WHEN THEY MOVED,
LIKE THUNDER.
AND NOW THEY'RE GONE.
IS THAT WHAT YOU MEAN?
LIKE THE CREATURES HERE.
ONCE THERE WERE MILLIONS
OF THEM,
NOW THERE'S ONE LEFT.
NANCY UNDERSTOOD.
ALWAYS IN THE PAST TENSE.
WHERE'S YOUR WIFE?
WHERE IS SHE NOW?
DEAD.
BURIED UP ON THE HILL.
IT KILLED HER.
WHEN?
WELL, A YEAR,
OR WAS IT TWO?
[ BEEPING ]
TREK TO ENTERPRISE.
Bridge to Captain.
Sulu here.
IT'S DEFINITE, MR. SULU.
THE INTRUDER CAN ASSUME
ANY SHAPE.
CREWMAN, YOU, MYSELF, ANYONE,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
Affirmative, Captain.
GO TO GQ FOUR.
General quarters four,
Captain.
THE CREATURE WAS TRYING
TO SURVIVE.
IT HAS THAT RIGHT,
DOESN'T IT?
KIRK TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
THREE TO BEAM UP.
THEY NEEDED SALT TO STAY ALIVE.
THERE WAS NO MORE SALT.
IT'S THE LAST ONE.
THE BUFFALO.
THERE IS NO DIFFERENCE.
THERE'S ONE, PROFESSOR.
YOUR CREATURE IS KILLING
MY PEOPLE.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, CONTINUING.
THE ENTERPRISE HAS BEEN INVADED
BY A CREATURE
CAPABLE OF ASSUMING ANY FORM,
WITH A CAPACITY TO PARALYZE
AND DRAW THE LIFE
FROM ANYONE OF US.
Deck five, section three.
Report.
SECURITY THREE "A" HERE.
THREE B INSIDE.
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
I'VE CHECKED EVERY FACE
ON THIS VESSEL.
IT WAS NOT CREWMAN I SAW.
YEOMAN RAND, HOW LONG
WAS THIS GREEN WITH YOU?
AS LONG AS HE--IT THOUGHT
IT COULD GET TO THE SALT
IN MY TRAY, SIR.
MR. SPOCK?
SUPPLIES OF SALT
HAVE BEEN SET OUT AS BAIT
AT ALL DECKS
AND ENGINEERING LEVELS, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, NO ONE OR NOTHING
HAS APPROACHED THEM AS YET.
DR. McCOY?
YES.
MEDICAL DEPARTMENT REPORT,
DOCTOR.
OH, WELL, WE COULD OFFER IT
SALT WITHOUT TRICKS.
THERE'S NO REASON FOR IT
TO ATTACK US.
YOUR ATTITUDE IS LAUDABLE,
DOCTOR,
BUT YOUR REASONING
IS RECKLESS.
THE CREATURE IS NOT DANGEROUS
WHEN FED.
NO, IT'S SIMPLY
TRYING TO SURVIVE
BY USING ITS NATURAL ABILITY
TO TAKE OTHER FORMS.
THE WAY THE CHAMELEON USES
ITS PROTECTIVE COLORING,
AN ABILITY RETAINED NO DOUBT
FROM ITS PRIMITIVE STATE,
THE WAY WE HAVE RETAINED
OUR INCISOR TEETH.
THEY WERE ONCE FANGS.
CERTAIN OF OUR MUSCLES
WERE DESIGNED FOR CHASE.
IT USES ITS ABILITY
THE WAY WE WOULD USE OUR MUSCLES
AND TEETH IF NECESSARY
TO STAY ALIVE.
AND LIKE US,
IT'S AN INTELLIGENT ANIMAL.
IT'S--THERE'S NO NEED
TO HUNT IT DOWN.
A VERY INTERESTING HYPOTHESIS,
DOCTOR.
[ WHISTLING ]
BRIEFING ROOM.
All the halls sealed off.
All weapons accounted for
and locked away.
Security four in effect
on every level.
Still no lead on intruder.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
CONTINUE THE SEARCH.
CRATER, WE DON'T KNOW WHO
OR WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
WE NEED YOUR HELP AND NOW.
I DEMANDED.
I EVEN BEGGED
THAT YOU GET OFF MY PLANET.
CAN YOU RECOGNIZE THIS THING
WHEN YOU SEE IT?
PROFESSOR, I'LL FOREGO CHARGES
UP TO THIS POINT.
BUT THIS CREATURE'S
ABOARD MY SHIP,
AND I'LL HAVE IT
OR I'LL HAVE YOUR SKIN OR BOTH.
NOW WHERE IS IT?
I LOVED NANCY VERY MUCH.
FEW WOMEN LIKE MY NANCY.
SHE LIVES IN MY DREAMS.
SHE WALKS AND SINGS
IN MY DREAMS.
AND IT BECOMES NANCY FOR YOU?
NOT BECAUSE OF TRICKS.
IT DOESN'T TRICK ME.
IT NEEDS LOVE
AS MUCH AS IT NEEDS SALT.
WHEN IT KILLED NANCY,
I ALMOST DESTROYED IT,
BUT IT ISN'T JUST A BEAST.
IT IS INTELLIGENT
AND THE LAST OF ITS KIND.
YOU BLEED TOO MUCH, CRATER.
YOU'RE TOO PURE AND NOBLE.
YOU SAVING THE LAST OF ITS KIND
OR HAS THIS BECOME
CRATER'S PRIVATE HEAVEN
HERE ON THIS PLANET?
THIS THING BECOMES WIFE, LOVER,
BEST FRIEND, WISEMAN, FOOL,
IDOL, SLAVE.
IT ISN'T A BAD LIFE
TO HAVE EVERYONE IN THE UNIVERSE
AT YOUR BECK AND CALL,
AND YOU WIN ALL THE ARGUMENTS.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HAVE YOU LEARNED
TO SEE THIS THING
IN WHATEVER FORM IT BECOMES?
YES.
ARE YOU GOING TO HELP US
FIND IT?
[ MUSIC ]
SORRY, I CAN'T.
I RECOMMEND WE USE TRUTH SERUM,
CAPTAIN.
DOCTOR?
WELL, I RESIST USING IT.
BUT IN THIS CASE, THE PROFESSOR
WILL GIVE US THE TRUTH.
TAKE HIM.
I'LL ACCOMPANY YOU, DOCTOR.
OH, YES, OF COURSE.
Captain Kirk to dispensary.
[ ALARM WAILING ]
IT WASN'T McCOY.
IT WAS THE CREATURE.
IT HIT ME.
CRATER GRABBED MY PHASER.
I WONDERED ABOUT McCOY.
DOUBT HAD CROSSED MY MIND.
CAPTAIN.
PROFESSOR CRATER.
DEAD.
BUT IT HAD YOU, TOO.
FORTUNATELY, MY ANCESTORS
SPAWNED IN ANOTHER OCEAN
THAN YOURS DID.
MY BLOOD CELLS
ARE QUITE DIFFERENT.
LEONARD.
LEONARD, WAKE UP.
PLEASE HELP ME.
HELP ME, LEONARD.
THEY'RE TRYING TO KILL ME.
DON'T LET THEM KILL ME.
WHO? EASY. EASY.
NOBODY'S GOING--
BUT YOU MUST HELP ME.
MOVE ASIDE, BONES.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE, JIM?
SHE'S NOT NANCY, BONES.
ARE YOU INSANE?
IT KILLED FOUR CREWMEN.
NOW CRATER.
IT?
THE CREATURE.
IT KILLS.
IT NEEDS SALT TO LIVE.
BONES, MOVE ASIDE.
NO.
MY GUESS IS SHE NEEDS MORE.
YOU WANT IT, NANCY?
COME AND GET IT.
YOU'RE FRIGHTENING HER, JIM.
NOT FRIGHT, HUNGER.
LOOK AT HER.
LEONARD, IF YOU LOVE ME,
MAKE HIM GO AWAY.
COME ON. YOU WANT THIS, NANCY?
COME ON, NANCY.
COME AND GET IT.
HERE IT IS.
-LEONARD, HELP ME.
-BONES, I CAN'T FIRE.
-GET OUT OF THE WAY.
-JIM, STOP IT.
-McCOY, GET OUT OF THE WAY.
-WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
-HELP ME.
-HERE, YOU WANT THESE?
-ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
-GET OUT OF THE WAY.
[ MUSIC ]
IT'S KILLING THE CAPTAIN.
SHOOT IT, DOCTOR. QUICKLY.
NO. NO.
IT'S KILLING THE CAPTAIN.
SHOOT, QUICK.
I WON'T SHOOT NANCY.
THIS IS NOT NANCY.
IF SHE WERE NANCY,
COULD SHE TAKE THIS?
STOP IT.
STOP IT, SPOCK.
IS THAT NANCY, DOCTOR?
NO.
[ SCREAMING ]
LEONARD.
LEONARD, NO.
LEONARD, PLEASE.
LORD, FORGIVE ME.
I'M SORRY, BONES.
[ MUSIC ]
READY TO LEAVE ORBIT,
CAPTAIN.
SOMETHING WRONG,
CAPTAIN?
I WAS THINKING
ABOUT THE BUFFALO, MR. SPOCK.
WARP ONE, MR. SULU.
WARP ONE, SIR.
LEAVING ORBIT.
[ BEEPING ]
[ MUSIC ]