CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 1533.6.
NOW MANEUVERING
TO COME ALONGSIDE
CARGO VESSEL ANTARES.
ITS CAPTAIN
AND FIRST OFFICER
ARE BEAMING OVER TO US
WITH AN UNUSUAL PASSENGER.
ALL RIGHT, CHIEF,
BEGIN MATERIALIZATION.
CAPTAIN RAMART,
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
THIS IS MY NAVIGATOR
TOM NELLIS.
HOW DO YOU DO?
AND THIS IS OUR
YOUNG CASTAWAY CHARLIE,
CHARLIE EVANS,
HIS DOSSIER.
MR. EVANS.
WE'VE HEARD
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT YOU.
WELCOME ABOARD.
Ramart:
WONDERFUL BOY,
CHARLIE.
IT'S BEEN A GREAT
PLEASURE HAVING HIM
ABOARD WITH US.
WHY, IT'S BEEN
A GREAT PLEASURE.
THE THINGS
THAT HE'S LEARNED...
ABSOLUTELY.
TO THINK THIS BOY
SPENT PRACTICALLY
HIS WHOLE LIFE
ALONE
ON THAT PLANET.
EVERYONE KILLED,
JUST A FEW
MICROTAPES
TO LEARN FROM.
HOW MANY HUMANS
LIKE ME ON THIS SHIP?
LIKE A WHOLE CITY
IN SPACE, CHARLIE.
OVER 400 IN THE CREW
OF A STARSHIP,
AREN'T THERE,
CAPTAIN?
428, TO BE EXACT.
IS THERE ANYTHING WE CAN DO
FOR YOU, CAPTAIN?
MEDICAL SUPPLIES,
PROVISIONS?
HUNDREDS!
ALL HUMAN, LIKE ME.
THAT'S EXCITING.
IS THAT THE RIGHT WORD?
THAT'S PERFECT.
IT'S THE EXACT WORD.
YOU SEE,
WE'D LIKE TO KEEP
CHARLIE WITH US.
BUT WITH HIS CLOSEST
LIVING RELATIVES
ON COLONY 5
AND YOUR VESSEL
GOING THAT WAY--
I'D LIKE TO SEE
YOUR SHIP NOW.
ALL OF IT, THE PEOPLE
AND EVERYTHING.
YOU KEEP INTERRUPTING,
MR. EVANS.
THAT'S
CONSIDERED WRONG.
I'M SORRY.
WE HAVE A LARGE SUPPLY
OF ENTERTAINMENT TAPES,
GENTLEMEN.
NO. WE'VE A TIGHT
SCHEDULE TO MAKE,
CAPTAIN.
JUST 20 OF US, WE'RE
MAKING OUT FINE.
THIS MUST BE
A SPACE FIRST.
A TRANSPORT SHIP
THAT DOESN'T NEED
ANYTHING?
NOTHING.
NOT EVEN
SARIAN BRANDY?
WE'RE FINE,
THANK YOU.
PLEASANT JOURNEY,
CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
YEOMAN RAND,
THIS IS CHARLES EVANS.
SHOW HIM
TO HIS QUARTERS
AND DROP HIS RECORDS OFF
AT DR. McCOY'S OFFICE,
IF YOU WILL.
YES, SIR.
COME WITH ME,
PLEASE.
A-ARE YOU A GIRL?
IS THAT A GIRL?
THAT'S A GIRL.
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 1533.7.
WE HAVE TAKEN ABOARD
AN UNUSUAL PASSENGER
FOR TRANSPORT
TO COLONY ALPHA 5--
CHARLES EVANS,
THE SOLE SURVIVOR
OF A TRANSPORT CRASH
14 YEARS AGO.
THE CHILD,
ALONE FROM AGE 3,
HAS NOT ONLY SURVIVED,
BUT HAS GROWN TO INTELLIGENT,
HEALTHY ADOLESCENCE.
TELL ME, UM, THE,
UH, SHIP'S SUPPLY
OF FOOD CONCENTRATES
COULDN'T HAVE
LASTED 14 YEARS.
AFTER THAT I FOUND
OTHER THINGS TO EAT,
JUST...GROWING AROUND.
AND YOU LEARNED TO TALK
BY JUST LISTENING
TO THE SHIP'S TAPES?
THE MEMORY BANKS
STILL WORKED.
THEY TALKED TO ME,
AND I TALKED BACK.
YOU'RE A 4-0.
A WHAT?
4-0, 100%, SOUND OF
WIND AND LIMB.
THAT--THAT
CAPTAIN...KIRK?
YEAH.
WHY DOES HE
CALL ME MR. EVANS?
'CAUSE THAT'S YOUR NAME.
HE'S NOT...
HE ISN'T LIKE
CAPTAIN RAMART.
WELL, NO.
CAPTAIN KIRK IS
ONE OF A KIND, CHARLIE.
DO YOU LIKE ME?
WHY NOT?
SOME...
THE OTHER SHIP,
THEY DIDN'T LIKE ME.
I TRIED.
I'M TRYING TO MAKE
PEOPLE LIKE ME.
I WANT THEM
TO LIKE ME.
MOST 17-YEAR-OLDS DO.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
I'LL SHOW YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
HEY. I'LL PUT
THE EQUIPMENT AWAY.
SEE YOU
IN THE REC ROOM, HUH?
YOU GOT
A DEAL, FRIEND.
ALL RIGHT.
HELLO.
I BROUGHT YOU A PRESENT.
OH, THANK YOU.
I REALLY APPRECIATE IT,
BUT...BUT I HAVE TO GO.
I-I'M ON DUTY.
DO YOU LIKE THAT KIND?
YES, I...
IT'S MY FAVORITE!
WHERE DID YOU GET IT?
THEY DON'T HAVE ANY
IN THE SHIP'S STORES.
IT'S A PRESENT.
I KNOW,
BUT WHERE DID...
GEE, I'M LATE, CHARLIE.
I--I REALLY HAVE TO GO.
CAN'T YOU STAY AND TALK
A LITTLE WHILE?
LOOK,
I'M OFF DUTY AT 1400.
WHY DON'T YOU JOIN ME
IN RECREATION ROOM 6,
DECK 3?
YOU GOT A DEAL,
FRIEND.
CHARLIE!
OH, I THOUGHT...
DON'T BE ANGRY.
I DIDN'T...
I WANTED...
CHARLIE, YOU--YOU...
YOU JUST DON'T GO AROUND
SLAPPING GIRLS ON THE...
IT'S O.K., BUT, UH,
JUST DON'T DO IT AGAIN.
DON'T BE ANGRY.
LOOK, WHY DON'T YOU
TELL CAPTAIN KIRK
OR DR. McCOY
WHAT YOU DID,
AND THEY'LL EXPLAIN IT
TO YOU, O.K.?
I WILL.
O.K.
McCoy: BUT TELL ME, WHAT
REASON WOULD HE HAVE TO LIE
IF THERE ARE THASIANS?
THAT IS A VERY
INTRIGUING QUESTION.
SCANNERS SHOW
NO DISTURBANCES
IN THIS QUADRANT,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
DR. McCOY, MR. SPOCK
IS WORKING OUT--
EXCUSE ME, CAPTAIN.
STATUS REPORT.
THANK YOU.
HE'S WORKING OUT
A TRAINING PROGRAM
FOR CHARLIE EVANS--
EARTH HISTORY,
HIS OWN BACKGROUND,
THAT SORT OF THING.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO GIVE HIM
THE NECESSARY
MEDICAL ORIENTATION
ON THE PROBLEMS
OF, UM...UH...
ADOLESCENCE.
WOULDN'T IT BE BETTER
FOR A FATHER IMAGE?
HE ALREADY
LOOKS UP TO YOU.
THE JOB IS YOURS, BONES.
FLATTERY WILL GET YOU
NOWHERE.
DOCTOR, DIDN'T THE BOY
MAKE ANY REFERENCE
AT ALL TO THASIANS?
DO YOU BELIEVE
THE LEGEND, MR. SPOCK,
THAT THASIANS STILL
EXIST ON THAT PLANET
IN SOME FORM?
CHARLIE'S VERY EXISTENCE
PROVES, IN FACT,
THERE MUST BE
SOME INTELLIGENT
FORM OF LIFE ON THASUS.
HE COULD NOT POSSIBLY
HAVE SURVIVED ALONE.
THE SHIP'S
FOOD CONCENTRATES
WOULD HAVE BEEN
EXHAUSTED IN A YEAR OR SO.
BY WHICH TIME HE WOULD
HAVE BEEN EATING
FRUITS, VEGETABLES.
PROBES OF THASUS INDICATE
VERY LITTLE EDIBLE LIFE.
PROBES HAVE
BEEN KNOWN WRONG.
DOCTOR, ARE YOU SPEAKING
SCIENTIFICALLY
OR EMOTIONALLY?
GENTLEMEN, THE FACT
IS THE BOY IS HERE
AND HE'S ALIVE
AND HE NEEDS OUR HELP.
AND HE NEEDS A GUIDE
AND HE NEEDS
AND FATHER IMAGE, JIM.
I'LL DEPEND ON
YOUR ASTUTE ABILITIES
TO SUPPLY HIM
WITH THAT...
OR FIND HIM ONE.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
[SINGING]
I'M SORRY.
I DID IT AGAIN,
DIDN'T I?
♪ ALL ROUND
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE ♪
♪ THERE'S SOMEONE WHO'S
IN SATAN'S 'GUISE ♪
♪ WHOSE DEVIL EARS
AND DEVIL EYES ♪
♪ COULD RIP YOUR HEART
FROM YOU ♪
♪ AT FIRST, HIS LOOK
COULD HYPNOTIZE ♪
♪ AND THEN HIS TOUCH
WOULD BARBARIZE ♪
♪ HIS ALIEN LOVE
WOULD VICTIMIZE ♪
♪ AND RIP YOUR HEART
FROM YOU ♪
♪ AND THAT'S WHY
FEMALE ASTRONAUTS ♪
♪ OH, VERY FEMALE ASTRONAUTS ♪
♪ WAIT TERRIFIED
AND OVERWROUGHT ♪
♪ TO FIND WHAT
HE WILL DO ♪
♪ OH, GIRLS IN SPACE,
BE WARY ♪
♪ BE WARY, BE WARY ♪
♪ GIRLS IN SPACE,
BE WARY ♪
♪ KNOW NOW WHAT
HE'LL DO ♪
ONE MORE TIME!
♪ NOW FROM A PLANET
OUT IN SPACE ♪
♪ THERE COMES A LAD,
NOT COMMONPLACE ♪
♪ A-SEEKING OUT
HIS FIRST EMBRACE ♪
♪ HE'S SAVING IT
FOR YOU ♪
♪ OH, CHARLIE'S
OUR NEW DARLING ♪
♪ OUR DARLING,
OUR DARLING ♪
♪ CHARLIE'S
OUR NEW DARLING ♪
♪ WE KNOW NOT
WHAT HE'LL DO ♪
[SILENCE]
WANT TO SEE SOMETHING?
TURN THEM OVER.
WELL, HOW DID
YOU DO THAT?
I CAN DO
A LOT OF CARD TRICKS.
ONE OF THE MEN
ON THE ANTARES
SHOWED ME.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT!
ON EARTH TODAY,
IT'S THANKSGIVING.
IF THE CREW HAS TO EAT
SYNTHETIC MEAT LOAF,
I WANT IT
TO LOOK LIKE TURKEY.
CHARLIE.
CAPTAIN?
I'M SUPPOSED
TO ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHY SHOULDN'T I...
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO EXPLAIN IT.
SAY IT RIGHT OUT.
THAT USUALLY WORKS.
WELL, IN THE CORRIDOR
I SAW...
WHEN JANICE...
WHEN YEOMAN RAND WAS...
WELL, I DID THAT TO HER.
SHE DIDN'T LIKE IT.
SHE SAID YOU'D
EXPLAIN IT TO ME.
ME?
I SEE, WELL, UM...
UH, THERE ARE THINGS
YOU CAN DO WITH A LADY,
UH, CHARLIE, THAT YOU...
UH, THERE'S NO RIGHT WAY
TO HIT A WOMAN.
I MEAN, MAN TO MAN
IS ONE THING,
BUT, UM, MAN AND WOMAN,
UH, IT'S, UH...
IT'S, UH...
WELL, IT'S, UH,
ANOTHER THING.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I DON'T KNOW.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
CAPTAIN KIRK.
EXCUSE ME.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN RAMART
OF THE ANTARES
IS ON "D" CHANNEL.
I'M ON MY WAY
TO THE BRIDGE NOW.
CAN I COME
WITH YOU?
I DON'T THINK SO,
CHARLIE.
I WON'T GET IN THE WAY.
CAN YOU BOOST
YOUR POWER, ANTARES?
WE'RE BARELY READING
YOUR TRANSMISSION.
WE ARE AT FULL OUTPUT,
ENTERPRISE.
I MUST SPEAK
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE,
CAPTAIN RAMART.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE JUST
BARELY IN RANGE.
I'VE GOT TO WARN--
RE-ESTABLISH CONTACT.
THEY'RE
NOT TRANSMITTING.
KEEP TRYING.
IT WASN'T VERY
WELL CONSTRUCTED.
SWEEP THE AREA
OF THE ANTARES
TRANSMISSION
WITH OUR PROBE
SCANNERS, MR. SPOCK.
AFFIRMATIVE,
CAPTAIN.
YOU THINK SOMETHING
HAPPENED TO THE ANTARES,
CHARLIE?
I DON'T KNOW.
PICKING UP SOME DEBRIS
ON OUR SCANNERS, CAPTAIN.
WHAT ABOUT THE ANTARES?
THE DEBRIS
IS WHAT'S LEFT
OF THE ANTARES.
CAPTAIN KIRK
FROM SHIP'S GALLEY.
KIRK HERE.
SIR, I PUT MEAT LOAF
IN THE OVENS.
THERE'S TURKEYS
IN THERE NOW,
REAL TURKEYS.
CHIEF, HAVE YOU--
HEH!
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 1535.8.
USFA HEADQUARTERS NOTIFIED
OF THE MYSTERIOUS LOSS
OF SCIENCE PROBE
VESSEL ANTARES.
YOUR MIND IS NOT
ON THE GAME, CAPTAIN.
CHECK.
THE ANTARES?
A SURVEY SHIP WITH
20 MEN ABOARD, LOST.
NO REASON.
OBVIOUSLY, CAPTAIN RAMART
WAS NOT AWARE
OF ANY TROUBLE.
I CAN'T FIGURE IT.
MY OWN CONCERN
IS MORE IMMEDIATE--
THE BOY.
I CAN USUALLY FOLLOW YOU,
MR. SPOCK,
BUT THIS TIME...
HE SEEMED
TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE ANTARES
BEFORE WE DID.
I'D CALL IT
A PRETTY LONG REACH
FOR EVIDENCE, MR. SPOCK.
COME IN, CHARLIE.
AND AGAIN.
CHECK.
CHECKMATE.
YOUR ILLOGICAL APPROACH
TO CHESS
DOES HAVE
ITS ADVANTAGES
ON OCCASION, CAPTAIN.
I PREFER TO CALL IT
INSPIRED.
AS YOU WISH.
AT ANY RATE,
THE GAME IS YOURS.
YOU PLAY CHESS, CHARLIE?
OH, I...
I WATCHED THEM PLAY
ON THE ANTARES.
CAN I TRY?
I PLACE YOU IN THE HANDS
OF OUR CHESS MASTER.
THE PRINCIPLES OF
THREE-DIMENSIONAL CHESS
ARE BASICALLY
MATHEMATIC, CHARLIE.
YOU PUT THE WHITE HERE
AND THE BLACK
ON THE SECONDARY LEVEL--
I KNOW WHAT IT IS.
LET'S PLAY.
VERY WELL.
THAT WAS A MISTAKE,
CHARLIE.
NO, IT WASN'T.
CHECKMATE.
NO, IT ISN'T.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
OH, CHARLIE.
I WAS LOOKING FOR YOU.
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
TINA LAWTON, YEOMAN THIRD CLASS.
CHARLIE EVANS.
HELLO, CHARLIE.
I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT ENJOY MEETING
SOMEONE YOUR OWN AGE.
CAN I TALK
TO YOU...ALONE?
CHARLIE, TINA'S...
EXCUSE ME.
I MUST BE
WANTED SOMEWHERE.
THAT WAS...
THAT WAS RUDE AND
COMPLETELY UNCALLED-FOR.
BUT I DON'T
NEED HER.
I WANT TO
TALK TO YOU.
THAT'S NO EXCUSE.
BETTER LEARN THAT
RIGHT NOW.
YOU HAVE TO LIVE
WITH PEOPLE, CHARLIE.
YOU'RE NOT ALONE ANYMORE.
BUT SHE'S NOT AS--
SHE DOESN'T--
SHE'S NOT THE SAME.
NOT LIKE YOU.
SHE'S--SHE'S JUST
A GIRL.
YOU'RE...
YOU SMELL LIKE A GIRL.
ALL THE OTHER GIRLS
ON THE SHIP, THEY...
THEY LOOK
JUST LIKE TINA.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE...
WHO LOOKS LIKE YOU.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND,
CAN'T YOU?
YOU KNOW ABOUT...
BEING WITH SOMEBODY?
WANTING TO BE?
IF I HAD
THE WHOLE UNIVERSE...
I'D GIVE IT TO YOU.
WHEN I SEE YOU, I...
I FEEL
LIKE I'M HUNGRY...
ALL OVER.
HUNGRY.
DO YOU KNOW
HOW THAT FEELS?
WHAT?
I WASN'T
SURE I SHOULD, UH,
TALK TO YOU ABOUT THIS.
YEOMAN, CHARLIE'S
A 17-YEAR-OLD BOY.
EXACTLY, AND HE'S--
I'VE ALREADY TALKED TO HIM
ABOUT THE SWAT.
IT'S NOT THAT.
CAPTAIN, I'VE SEEN
THE LOOK BEFORE,
AND IF SOMETHING
ISN'T DONE,
SOONER OR LATER
I'M GOING TO
HAVE TO HURT HIM.
TELL HIM
TO LEAVE ME ALONE.
HMM.
THAT WOULDN'T BE GOOD
FOR HIM RIGHT NOW.
YOU SEE,
I'M HIS FIRST CRUSH,
HIS FIRST LOVE,
AND HIS FIRST--
YES, YEOMAN,
I'LL TALK TO HIM.
I'LL LOOK INTO IT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
COME IN, CHARLIE.
UH, CHARLIE...
CHARLIE,
DO YOU KNOW, UH...
ANYTHING ABOUT
THIS CHESS PIECE?
DO YOU NOTICE ANYTHING
PECULIAR IN THEM...
WHEN WE WERE USING THEM
THIS AFTERNOON?
NO, SIR. IS THAT ALL?
UH, NO. NO, NO.
SIT DOWN.
CHARLIE, BEING 17
IS MORE THAN HOW MANY
YEARS YOU'VE LIVED.
IT'S A WHOLE
OTHER THING.
DR. McCOY COULD PROBABLY
EXPLAIN THE
BIOLOGICAL CONDITIONS.
WELL, LET'S--LET'S
USE A SPECIFIC.
YEOMAN RAND IS A WOMAN.
OH, I WON'T HIT HER
LIKE THAT ANYMORE.
NO. THERE'S MORE TO IT
THAN THAT.
EVERYTHING
I DO OR SAY IS WRONG.
I'M IN THE WAY,
I DON'T KNOW THE RULES,
AND WHEN
I LEARN SOMETHING
AND TRY TO DO IT,
SUDDENLY I'M WRONG!
NOW WAIT, WAIT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I AM...
OR WHAT
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE
OR EVEN WHO.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I HURT SO MUCH INSIDE
ALL THE TIME.
YOU'LL LIVE, BELIEVE ME.
THERE'S
NOTHING WRONG WITH YOU
THAT HASN'T GONE WRONG
WITH EVERY OTHER
HUMAN MALE
SINCE THE MODEL
FIRST CAME OUT.
WHAT IF YOU
CARE FOR SOMEONE?
WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU GO SLOW.
YOU, UH...
YOU BE GENTLE.
I MEAN,
IT'S NOT A ONE-WAY
STREET, YOU KNOW,
HOW YOU FEEL
AND THAT'S ALL.
IT'S HOW THE GIRL
FEELS, TOO.
DON'T PRESS, CHARLIE.
IF THE GIRL FEELS...
ANYTHING FOR YOU AT ALL,
YOU'LL KNOW IT.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU DON'T THINK JANICE...
YOU...
SHE COULD LOVE ME!
SHE'S NOT THE GIRL,
CHARLIE.
THE YEARS ARE WRONG,
FOR ONE THING,
AND THERE
ARE OTHER THINGS.
SHE CAN.
NO, CHARLIE.
SHE IS.
NO.
BUT IF I DID
WHAT YOU SAID!
IF I WAS GENTLE!
CHARLIE, THERE ARE
A MILLION THINGS
IN THIS UNIVERSE
YOU CAN HAVE
AND THERE ARE
A MILLION THINGS
YOU CAN'T HAVE.
IT'S NO FUN FACING THAT,
BUT THAT'S THE WAY
THINGS ARE.
THEN WHAT
AM I GOING TO DO?
HANG ON TIGHT
AND SURVIVE.
EVERYBODY DOES.
YOU DON'T.
EVERYBODY, CHARLIE.
ME, TOO.
I'M TRYING,
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
KIRK HERE.
Uhura:
YOU ASKED TO BE NOTIFIED
WHEN WE WERE TO MAKE OUR
COURSE ADJUSTMENTS, SIR.
ASK MR. SPOCK
TO SEE TO IT.
[CLICK]
CHARLIE,
COME ON WITH ME.
YOU GOT TO SLAP
THE FLOOR
TO ABSORB THE ENERGY
WHEN YOU FALL.
GO AHEAD, TRY IT.
LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE,
IT TAKES PRACTICE.
CHARLIE, TRY AGAIN.
GOOD. THAT'S
MUCH BETTER.
OK. NOW I'LL SHOW
YOU A SHOULDER ROLL.
TRY THAT.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT.
WELL, IT MAKES IT HARD
TO TEACH YOU--
I DON'T WANT
TO DO THAT.
ALL RIGHT, CHARLIE.
LESSON'S OVER FOR TODAY.
YOU WERE
GOING TO TEACH ME
HOW TO FIGHT.
YOU HAVE TO LEARN
TO PROTECT YOURSELF
IN A FALL BEFORE I DO THAT.
AND IT'S MORE
THAN JUST TEACHING YOU
HOW TO DEFEND YOURSELF.
CHARLIE,
I WANT YOU TO L--
CHARLIE?
HEY, SAM,
LET ME BORROW YOU
FOR A COUPLE
EASY THROWS,
ALL RIGHT?
WATCH THIS, CHARLIE.
THAT WASN'T SO BAD,
WAS IT?
NOW I'LL THROW HIM.
HERE WE GO, SAM.
THAT LOOKS HARD.
AW!
COME ON, CHARLIE.
TRY IT.
ATTABOY.
LET'S GO.
OH!
[SAM LAUGHS]
THAT WASN'T SO BAD,
WAS IT?
DON'T LAUGH AT ME.
COOL OFF.
DON'T LAUGH AT ME!
CHARLIE.
HE SHOULDN'T
HAVE DONE THAT.
IT'S NOT NICE
TO LAUGH AT PEOPLE.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIM, CHARLIE?
HE'S GONE.
THAT'S NO ANSWER.
HE'S GONE!
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO DO THAT.
HE MADE ME DO IT!
HE LAUGHED AT ME.
BRIDGE.
KIRK HERE.
TWO MEN FROM SECURITY,
ON THE DOUBLE.
AFFIRMATIVE.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO TO ME?
I'M CONFINING YOU
TO QUARTERS.
I WANT YOU
TO STAY THERE.
I WON'T LET THEM
HURT ME.
I'LL MAKE THEM
GO AWAY, TOO.
THEY WON'T HURT YOU,
CHARLIE.
THEY'LL TAKE YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
GO WITH THEM.
NO!
GO TO YOUR QUARTERS.
HE WAS GOING
TO HURT ME.
GO TO YOUR QUARTERS,
OR I'LL PICK YOU UP
AND CARRY YOU THERE.
I WON'T LET YOU.
THAT'S YOUR CHOICE,
CHARLIE.
I WON'T LET THEM
HURT ME.
THEY WON'T HURT YOU.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Uhura:
CAPTAIN KIRK?
KIRK HERE.
SECURITY REPORTS
THAT ALL PHASER WEAPONS
HAVE DISAPPEARED.
SHALL I REPEAT, CAPTAIN?
NO. I HEARD YOU.
HAVE DR. McCOY
AND MR. SPOCK MEET ME
IN THE BRIEFING ROOM.
THASIANS HAVE BEEN
REFERRED TO IN
OUR RECORDS
AS HAVING THE POWER
TO TRANSMUTE OBJECTS
OR RENDER SUBSTANCES
INVISIBLE.
IT'S GENERALLY
BEEN REGARDED AS LEGEND,
BUT CHARLIE SEEMS
TO POSSESS THIS SAME POWER.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
THAT CHARLIE ISN'T
AN EARTH BEING,
THAT HE'S A THASIAN?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO,
NOT UNLESS THEY'RE EXACTLY
LIKE EARTHLINGS.
THE DEVELOPMENT
OF HIS FINGERS AND TOES
EXACTLY MATCHES
PRESENT DEVELOPMENT
OF MAN'S ON EARTH.
AGREED.
WELL,
WHATEVER HE IS,
WE HAVE SOME IDEA
OF THE POWER HE HAS.
I KNOW WHAT I SAW HIM DO
IN THE GYMNASIUM.
CONSIDERING THE EFFECT
A NORMAL ADOLESCENT HAS
ON A HOME, CHARLIE,
WITH THE POWER HE HAS--
SHORT-TEMPERED,
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND.
HE NEEDS, HE WANTS.
NOTHING HAPPENS
FAST ENOUGH.
THE PROBABILITY IS
HE'S RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE ANTARES,
WHICH WOULD INDICATE
TOTAL DISREGARD
FOR HUMAN LIFE.
HE DOESN'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT LIFE IS.
HE'S A BOY.
WELL, WHAT DO WE DO
WITH THIS BOY, JIM?
HOW DO WE KEEP HIM
CAGED UP?
IT GOES EVEN FURTHER,
DOCTOR.
WE CAN'T TAKE HIM
TO EARTH COLONY 5.
IMAGINE WHAT HE'D DO
IN AN OPEN, NORMAL
ENVIRONMENT.
TALK TO HIM,
LISTEN TO HIM.
HE'S A BOY
IN A MAN'S BODY
TRYING TO BE ADULT,
THE ADOLESCENT IN HIM
GETTING IN THE WAY.
WITH A WEAPON IN HIM,
WHICH COULD DESTROY
YOU OR ANYONE
ANYWHERE ON THIS SHIP.
WELL, FOR THE MOMENT
HE'S STOPPED.
YOU'RE AN AUTHORITY
HE RESPECTS, JIM.
AGREED.
THE STRUGGLE MUST REMAIN
BETWEEN YOU AND HIM.
SHOULD ANY OF US
INTERFERE...
YOU WANTED TO ASK ME
SOMETHING, HE SAID.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE ANTARES, CHARLIE?
WHY?
ANSWER ME.
YES.
THERE WAS A WARPED
BAFFLE-PLATE
ON THE SHIED
OF THEIR
ENERGY PILE.
I MADE IT GO AWAY.
IT WOULD'VE
BLOWN UP ANYWAY.
WELL, THEY WEREN'T
NICE TO ME!
THEY WANTED
TO GET RID OF ME.
THEY DON'T NOW.
WHAT ABOUT US, CHARLIE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WE'RE IN THE HANDS
OF AN ADOLESCENT.
LIEUTENANT,
RAISE COLONY 5.
I WANT TO SPEAK DIRECTLY
TO THE GOVERNOR.
NAVIGATOR, LAY IN A COURSE
AWAY FROM COLONY 5.
BUY ME SOME TIME.
YES, SIR.
AAH!
SPOCK, GET THE DOCTOR
UP HERE ON THE DOUBLE.
HOW BAD IS IT?
I THINK
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SIR.
SIR, THERE'S NO REASON
FOR THAT PANEL
TO CROSS-CIRCUIT
LIKE THAT.
I CHECKED IT OVER MYSELF
NOT 15 MINUTES AGO.
CAPTAIN, I CAN'T FEED
ANY COURSE COORDINATES
INTO THE PANEL, SIR.
IT REJECTS
THE COURSE CHANGE.
HELM DOESN'T
RESPOND EITHER, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, YOU
GETTING READINGS
ON YOUR INSTRUMENTS?
YES, SIR. THERE'S A--
TIGER, TIGER,
BURNING BRIGHT
IN THE FOREST
OF THE NIGHT.
MR. SPOCK.
I'M TRYING TO--
SATURN RINGS
AROUND MY HEAD,
DOWN A ROAD
THAT'S MARTIAN RED.
YOU'RE TRYING
TO CHANGE COURSE, CAPTAIN.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
I WANT TO GET TO COLONY 5
AS SOON AS WE CAN.
RELEASE THE TRANSMITTER.
YOU DON'T NEED ALL THAT
SUBSPACE CHATTER.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
SPOCK CALLS ME
TO THE BRIDGE
AND THEN GOES INTO SOME
KIND OF POETRY.
SEE TO HER, DOCTOR.
ONCE UPON
A MIDNIGHT DREARY
WHILE I PONDERED
WEAK AND WEARY...
VERY NICE,
MR. EARS.
OH, I CAN MAKE HIM
DO ANYTHING--
WHIRL AROUND,
LAUGH, ANYTHING.
THAT'S ENOUGH, CHARLIE.
DON'T YOU THINK
HE'S FUNNY?
I THINK HE'S FUNNY.
LEAVE MY CREW ALONE.
JIM, HE'LL
SOON REACH A POINT
WHERE
HE WON'T BACK DOWN.
I KNOW.
CHARLIE, WHAT'S WRONG?
I HAVE SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
PINK IS YOUR FAVORITE,
ISN'T IT?
YOU DON'T
WALK INTO A ROOM
WITHOUT KNOCKING.
DON'T EVER
LOCK YOUR DOOR
ON ME AGAIN, JANICE.
I LOVE YOU.
I'LL LOCK IT
WHEN I PLEASE.
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT
ANYWAY?
YOU.
I ONLY WANT
TO BE NICE TO YOU.
I CAN GIVE YOU ANYTHING.
JUST--JUST TELL ME.
I WANT YOU
TO GET OUT.
BUT I ONLY WANT
TO BE NICE TO YOU.
GET OUT, CHARLIE.
SPOCK.
I CAN'T MAKE IT
ANY PLAINER
THAN THAT.
I LOVE YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE WORD MEANS.
THEN SHOW ME.
NO!
CHARLIE.
WHY DID SHE DO THAT?
I LOVED HER,
BUT SHE WASN'T NICE
AT ALL.
WHAT YOU DID
WASN'T NICE EITHER,
BUT I STILL NEED YOU,
CAPTAIN.
THE ENTERPRISE ISN'T
QUITE LIKE THE ANTARES.
RUNNING THE ANTARES
WAS EASY.
YOU HAVE TO BE NICE.
ALL RIGHT?
MR. SPOCK?
MY LEGS--
THEY'RE BROKEN.
LET HIM GO, TOO,
CHARLIE.
WHY?
BECAUSE I'M
TELLING YOU TO.
YOU NEED ME
TO RUN THE SHIP,
AND I NEED HIM.
IF YOU TRY
TO HURT ME AGAIN,
I'LL MAKE A LOT
OF PEOPLE GO AWAY.
AND WHAT ABOUT
YEOMAN JANICE?
IS SHE DEAD?
GONE?
DESTROYED?
I WON'T TELL YOU.
GROWING UP
ISN'T SO MUCH.
I'M NOT A MAN,
AND I CAN DO ANYTHING!
YOU CAN'T.
I'LL ACTIVATE
THE FORCE FIELD MYSELF.
YOU CAN RETURN
TO YOUR SECTION.
HE HAD A MEAN LOOK.
I HAD TO FREEZE HIM.
I LIKE HAPPY LOOKS.
AREN'T YOU COMING IN?
THAT WASN'T NICE.
YOU'LL BE SORRY.
YOU WAIT.
YOU'LL SEE.
YOU'LL BE SORRY
YOU DID THAT.
YOU WILL.
AAH!
[LAUGHING]
NO.
NO LAUGHING!
[SILENT]
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
[MOANING]
CAPTAIN KIRK...
MY INSTRUMENTS SHOW
WE'RE RECEIVING A MESSAGE
ON SUBSPACE FREQUENCY 3,
SHIP-TO-SHIP.
I CAN'T HEAR IT, SIR.
YOU'RE CREATING
THAT MESSAGE, CHARLIE,
OR YOU'RE BLOCKING ONE
THAT'S COMING IN.
IT'S MY GAME, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE TO FIND OUT.
LIKE YOU SAID, THAT'S
HOW THE GAME'S PLAYED.
YOU CAN HAVE IT NOW.
I'VE LOCKED ON COURSE
FOR COLONY 5 AGAIN.
I'VE WAITED LONG ENOUGH.
I'M GOING
TO TAKE HIM ON.
YOU DON'T HAVE
ANY SPECIAL IMMUNITY.
NOT ANYMORE.
PUSH FAR ENOUGH,
HE'D SEND YOU
TO OBLIVION, TOO.
MR. SPOCK?
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
WAIT A MINUTE.
DOES CHARLIE...
NOW, WAIT...
SPOCK, HAS HE
DONE AWAY WITH ANYBODY
SINCE HE TOOK OVER?
NOT SO FAR AS
WE KNOW.
THEN MAYBE HE CAN'T.
COULD BE
HE'S OVERREACHED HIMSELF.
IT'S A BIG SHIP.
HE'S TAKEN FULL CONTROL.
IF WE COULD
TAX HIS POWER--
TURN ON EVERY
DEVICE ON THE SHIP,
EVERY CIRCUIT,
EVERY LIGHT,
ALL OF IT--
AND WHILE
HE'S FIGHTING THAT,
IF I COULD
DISTRACT HIM,
MAYBE YOU COULD
TRANQUILIZE HIM,
KEEP HIM UNDER,
UNTIL WE REACH
COLONY 5.
RISKY, JIM.
IF WE DON'T TRY,
DOCTOR,
HE'LL GET RID OF US
ANYWAY.
THERE'S NO CHOICE,
GENTLEMEN,
NONE AT ALL.
I CAN MAKE YOU ALL
GO AWAY...
ANYTIME I WANT TO.
GET OUT OF MY CHAIR,
CHARLIE,
AND GET OUT
OF IT NOW.
I'VE GOT YOUR SHIP,
CAPTAIN.
MAYBE, CHARLIE,
BUT I DON'T THINK
YOU CAN HANDLE ANY MORE.
I THINK YOU'VE
REACHED YOUR LIMIT
AND CAN'T TAKE ON
ONE MORE THING.
BUT YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO.
I COULD'VE SENT
YOU AWAY BEFORE,
BUT I DIDN'T.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO TAKE ME ON.
DON'T MAKE ME
DO IT NOW!
YOU'VE GOT MY SHIP,
AND I WANT IT BACK.
I WANT MY CREW BACK
WHOLE,
IF I HAVE TO BREAK
YOUR NECK TO DO IT!
DON'T PUSH ME.
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
AAH.
SORRY.
I'M SORRY...
BUT...
AAH!
[RECEIVER CRACKLES]
STOP THAT.
I SAID STOP IT!
CAPTAIN,
THE NAVIGATION CONSOLE
IS CLEAR NOW.
THE SHIP IS
ANSWERING THE HELM.
SIR, SOMETHING OFF
OUR STARBOARD BOW.
THE MESSAGE SAYS
THEY'RE FROM THASUS.
OH.
CAPTAIN, HOW DID I--
IT'S ALL RIGHT, YEOMAN.
SENSORS SHOW
SOMETHING'S THERE.
DEFLECTORS INDICATE
NO SOLID SUBSTANCE.
NO!
OH, NO, PLEASE...
DON'T LET THEM TAKE ME.
I CAN'T LIVE WITH THEM
ANYMORE!
YOU'RE MY FRIENDS.
YOU SAID YOU WERE
MY FRIENDS, REMEMBER?
WHEN I CAME ABOARD!
PLEASE...
I WANT TO GO HOME.
TAKE ME HOME.
I HAVE TAKEN MY FORM
CENTURIES AGO,
SO THAT I MAY
COMMUNICATE WITH YOU.
WE DID NOT REALIZE
UNTIL TOO LATE
THAT THE BOY HAD GONE,
AND WE ARE SADDENED
THAT HIS ESCAPE
COST THE LIVES
OF THE FIRST SHIP.
WE COULD NOT HELP THEM,
BUT WE HAVE RETURNED
YOUR PEOPLE
AND YOUR SHIP TO YOU.
EVERYTHING IS AS IT WAS.
I WON'T DO IT AGAIN.
PLEASE, I'LL BE GOOD.
I WON'T EVER
DO IT AGAIN.
I'M SORRY
ABOUT THE ANTARES.
I'M SORRY!
WHEN I CAME ABOARD.
PLEASE...
I WANT TO GO WITH YOU.
HELP ME!
THE BOY BELONGS
WITH HIS OWN KIND.
THAT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE.
WITH TRAINING,
WE CAN TEACH HIM
TO LIVE IN OUR SOCIETY.
IF HE CAN BE TAUGHT
NOT TO USE HIS POWER...
WE GAVE HIM POWER
SO HE COULD LIVE.
HE WILL USE IT
ALWAYS,
AND HE WOULD
DESTROY YOU
AND YOUR KIND,
OR YOU
WOULD BE FORCED
TO DESTROY HIM
TO SAVE YOURSELVES.
IS THERE NOTHING
YOU CAN DO?
WE OFFER HIM LIFE,
AND WE WILL
TAKE CARE OF HIM.
COME, CHARLES.
OH, PLEASE...
DON'T LET THEM TAKE ME.
I CAN'T EVEN TOUCH THEM!
JANICE...
THEY CAN'T FEEL.
NOT LIKE YOU!
THEY DON'T LOVE!
PLEASE...
I WANT TO STAY...
STAY...
STAY.
Uhura:
CHARLIE'S BACK ON BOARD
THE THASIAN SHIP, SIR.
THEY SIGNALED
THEY'RE LEAVING.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, YEOMAN.
IT'S ALL OVER NOW.