[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1312.4.
THE IMPOSSIBLE HAS HAPPENED.
FROM DIRECTLY AHEAD,
WE'RE PICKING UP
A RECORDED DISTRESS SIGNAL,
THE CALL LETTERS OF A VESSEL
WHICH HAS BEEN MISSING
FOR OVER TWO CENTURIES.
DID ANOTHER EARTH SHIP
ONCE PROBE OUT OF THE GALAXY
AS WE INTEND TO DO?
WHAT HAPPENED TO IT OUT THERE?
IS THIS SOME WARNING
THEY'VE LEFT BEHIND?
YOUR MOVE, CAPTAIN.
WE SHOULD HAVE INTERCEPTED
BY NOW.
THE BRIDGE SAID THEY'D CALL.
I'LL HAVE YOU CHECKMATED
AT YOUR NEXT MOVE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HAVE I EVEN MENTIONED YOU PLAY
A VERY IRRITATING GAME OF CHESS,
MR. SPOCK?
IRRITATING.
AH, YES.
ONE OF YOUR EARTH EMOTIONS.
YOU'RE CERTAIN YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT IRRITATION IS?
THE FACT ONE OF MY ANCESTORS
MARRIED A HUMAN FEMALE.
TERRIBLE HAVING BAD BLOOD
LIKE THAT.
[ WHISTLE BLOWING ]
Bridge to briefing lounge.
OBJECT IS NOW WITHIN
TRACTOR BEAM RANGE.
NO VISUAL CONTACT, MR. KELSO?
NO, SIR.
IT'S TOO SMALL TO BE A VESSEL.
IT ONLY READS ABOUT
ONE METER IN DIAMETER.
NOT LARGE ENOUGH
EVEN FOR A LIFE BOAT.
SMALL ENOUGH TO BRING IT ABOARD,
SIR, IF YOU WANNA RISK IT.
LOCK ONTO IT, MR. KELSO.
[ BEEPING ]
MATERIAL LASER READY, SIR.
BRING IT ABOARD.
[ BEEPING ]
OLD-STYLE SHIP RECORDER
THAT COULD BE EJECTED
WHEN SOMETHING THREATENED
THE SHIP.
MORE LIKE DESTROYED THE SHIP
IN THIS CASE.
LOOK AT IT.
BURNT, PITTED.
LET'S HOPE ITS TAPES ARE INTACT.
WE'LL FEED IT
THROUGH MR. SPOCK'S COMPUTER.
YES, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
IT'S BEGUN TRANSMITTING, SIR.
FLASH THE BRIDGE!
PUT ALL DECKS ON THE ALERT!
[ SIREN ]
[ MUSIC ]
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION:
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[ MUSIC ]
[ SIREN ]
HOLD IT, JIM.
GETTING INTO SHAPE?
YEAH. WELL, I FIGURED
YOU WEREN'T ON THE BRIDGE.
KELSO'S VOICE SOUNDED
A LITTLE NERVOUS.
WELL, UH, YOU FINISHED THE GAME?
MMM. HE PLAYED MOST ILLOGICALLY.
HIS NEXT MOVE SHOULD HAVE BEEN
THE ROOK.
YOU'RE RELIEVED, MR. ALDEN.
ACKNOWLEDGED, MR. MITCHELL.
SCREEN ON.
SCREEN ON, SIR.
[ FAINT BEEPING ]
APPROACHING GALAXY EDGE, SIR.
NEUTRALIZE WARP, MR. MITCHELL.
HOLD THIS POSITION.
NEUTRALIZED WARP, SIR.
ADDRESS INTERCRAFT.
INTERCRAFT OPEN.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
THE OBJECT WE ENCOUNTERED
IS A SHIP'S DISASTER RECORDER
APPARENTLY EJECTED
FROM THE SS VALIANT
ALMOST 200 YEARS AGO.
TAPES ARE BURNT OUT.
TRYING THE MEMORY BANKS.
WE HOPE TO LEARN
FROM THE RECORDER
WHAT THE VALIANT WAS DOING HERE
AND WHAT DESTROYED THE VESSEL.
WE'LL MOVE OUT INTO OUR PROBE
AS SOON AS WE HAVE
THOSE ANSWERS.
ALL DECKS, STAND BY.
OUR DEPARTMENT HEADS, SIR.
YOU WANTED EVERYBODY
ON THE BRIDGE
BEFORE WE LEFT THE GALAXY.
JONES.
THE NAME'S SMITH, SIR.
ASTRO SCIENCES STANDING BY,
CAPTAIN.
ENGINEERING DIVISION READY,
AS ALWAYS.
LIFE SCIENCES READY, SIR.
THIS IS DR. DEHNER
WHO JOINED THE SHIP
AT THE ALDEBARAN COLONY.
PSYCHIATRY, CAPTAIN.
MY ASSIGNMENT
IS TO STUDY CREW REACTION
IN EMERGENCY CONDITIONS.
GETTING SOMETHING
FROM THE RECORDER NOW.
IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY,
I'D BE INTERESTED
IN HOW THAT CREW REACTED, TOO.
WELL, IMPROVING THE BREED,
DOCTOR, IS THAT YOUR LINE?
I HEARD THAT'S MORE
YOUR SPECIALTY, COMMANDER,
LINE INCLUDED.
WALKING FREEZER UNIT.
DECODING MEMORY BANKS.
I'LL TRY TO INTERPOLATE.
THE VALIANT HAD ENCOUNTERED
A MAGNETIC SPACE STORM
AND WAS BEING SWEPT
IN THIS DIRECTION.
THE OLD IMPULSE ENGINES
WEREN'T STRONG ENOUGH.
SWEPT PAST THIS POINT,
ABOUT A HALF LIGHT-YEAR
OUT OF THE GALAXY.
THEY WERE THROWN CLEAR,
TURNED AND HEADED BACK
INTO THE GALAXY HERE.
I'M NOT GETTING IT ALL.
THE TAPES
ARE PRETTY BADLY BURNED.
SOUNDS LIKE THE SHIP
HAD ENCOUNTERED
SOME UNKNOWN FORCE.
NOW, ORDERS, COUNTER ORDERS.
REPEATED URGENT REQUESTS
FOR INFORMATION
FROM THE SHIP'S COMPUTER RECORDS
FOR ANYTHING CONCERNING ESP
IN HUMAN BEINGS.
EXTRASENSORY PERCEPTION?
DR. DEHNER, HOW ARE YOU ON ESP?
IN TESTS I'VE TAKEN,
MY ESP RATED RATHER HIGH.
I'M ASKING WHAT YOU KNOW
ABOUT ESP.
IT IS A FACT THAT SOME PEOPLE
CAN SENSE FUTURE HAPPENINGS,
READ THE BACKS OF PLAYING CARDS
AND SO ON.
BUT THE ESPER CAPACITY
IS ALWAYS QUITE LIMITED.
SEVERE DAMAGE.
SEVEN CREWMEN DEAD.
NO, MAKE THAT SIX.
ONE CREWMAN SEEMED
TO HAVE RECOVERED.
THAT'S WHEN THEY BECAME
INTERESTED
IN EXTRASENSORY PERCEPTION.
MORE THAN INTERESTED,
ALMOST FRANTIC ABOUT IT.
[ FREQUENCY DISTORTION ]
NO, THIS--THIS MUST BE GARBLED.
I GET SOMETHING ABOUT DESTRUCT.
I MUST HAVE READ IT WRONG.
IT SOUNDED LIKE THE CAPTAIN
GIVING AN ORDER
TO DESTROY HIS OWN SHIP.
[ MUSIC ]
COMMENTS?
THE ONLY FACT WE HAVE FOR SURE
IS THAT THE SS VALIANT
WAS DESTROYED.
THAT'S PROBABLY
THE BEST ARGUMENT
TO CONTINUE THE PROBE.
OTHER VESSELS WILL BE HEADING
OUT HERE SOMEDAY,
AND THEY'LL HAVE TO KNOW
WHAT THEY'LL BE FACING.
WE'RE LEAVING THE GALAXY,
MR. MITCHELL.
AHEAD, WARP FACTOR ONE.
[ BEEPS ]
[ MUSIC ]
FORCE FIELD OF SOME KIND.
WE'RE COMING UP ON IT FAST.
SENSOR BEAM ON.
SENSOR BEAM ON, SIR.
DEFLECTORS FULL INTENSITY.
DEFLECTORS SAY
THERE'S SOMETHING THERE.
SENSORS SAY THERE ISN'T.
DENSITY NEGATIVE.
RADIATION NEGATIVE.
ENERGY NEGATIVE.
WHATEVER IT IS,
CONTACT IN 12 SECONDS.
[ MUSIC ]
GRAVITATION ON AUTOMATIC.
[ EXPLOSIONS ]
EMERGENCY STATIONS.
ALL DECKS ON FIRE ALERT.
NEUTRALIZE CONTROLS.
KELSO, PUT IT ON MANUAL.
ANY RADIATION? ANYTHING?
NEGATIVE!
HELMSMAN, TAKE US OUT OF HERE!
HELMSMAN!
LATERAL POWER!
TAKE DAMAGE REPORTS.
DAMAGE CONTROL REPORTS,
ALL STATIONS!
Gravity control
switching to battery.
SOMETHING HIT ME,
LIKE AN ELECTRICAL CHARGE.
HE'S ALIVE.
APPEARS TO BE IN SHOCK.
Engineering Deck Three,
can you give damage report?
The sensor beams.
Full power on the deflectors.
MAIN ENGINES ARE OUT, SIR.
WE'RE ON EMERGENCY POWER CELLS.
CASUALTIES, NINE DEAD.
Gravity is down to .8.
All decks,
this is Bridge engineering.
Due to the emergency
conditions...
GARY. GARY, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M A LITTLE WEAK
FOR SOME REASON, JIM,
BUT I FEEL ALL RIGHT NOW.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1312.9.
SHIP'S CONDITION, HEADING BACK
ON IMPULSE POWER ONLY.
MAIN ENGINES BURNED OUT.
THE SHIP'S SPACE WARP ABILITY:
GONE.
EARTH BASES
WHICH WERE ONLY DAYS AWAY
ARE NOW YEARS IN THE DISTANCE.
OUR OVERRIDING QUESTION NOW IS
WHAT DESTROYED THE VALIANT?
THEY LIVED THROUGH THE BARRIER,
JUST AS WE HAVE.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM
AFTER THAT?
[ MUSIC ]
[ FREQUENCY BEEPING ]
AUTOPSY REPORT, SIR.
EACH CASE SHOWED DAMAGE
TO THE BODY'S NEURAL CIRCUIT.
AN AREA OF THE BRAIN
WAS BURNED OUT.
AND YOU,
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
YES. MITCHELL, TOO,
EXCEPT FOR HIS EYES.
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND A REASON
FOR THAT NOW,
AND WHY, OUT OF OUR WHOLE CREW,
ONLY CERTAIN PEOPLE
WERE AFFECTED.
I THINK WE'VE FOUND THAT ANSWER,
DOCTOR.
YOU MENTIONED THAT TESTS SHOW
THAT YOU HAVE A HIGH DEGREE
OF EXTRASENSORY PERCEPTION.
SO DO THE RECORDS OF THE OTHERS.
GARY MITCHELL HAS THE HIGHEST
ESPER RATING OF ALL.
IF YOU'RE SUGGESTING
THERE'S ANYTHING DANGEROUS--
BEFORE THE VALIANT
WAS DESTROYED,
ITS CAPTAIN
WAS FRANTICALLY SEARCHING
FOR ESP INFORMATION ON HIS CREW.
ESPERS ARE SIMPLY PEOPLE
WITH FLASHES OF INSIGHT.
ARE THERE NOT ALSO THOSE
WHO SEEM TO SEE
THROUGH SOLID OBJECTS,
CAUSE FIRES TO START
SPONTANEOUSLY?
THERE'S NOTHING ABOUT IT
THAT COULD POSSIBLY MAKE
A PERSON DANGEROUS.
DR. DEHNER IS SPEAKING
OF NORMAL ESP POWER.
PERHAPS YOU KNOW
OF ANOTHER KIND?
DO WE KNOW FOR SURE, DOCTOR,
THAT THERE ISN'T ANOTHER KIND?
[ MUSIC ]
HELLO, JIM.
HEY, YOU LOOK WORRIED.
I'VE BEEN WORRIED ABOUT YOU
EVER SINCE THAT NIGHT
ON DENEB IV.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH, SHE WAS NOVA, THAT ONE.
NOT NEARLY AS MANY AFTER-EFFECTS
THIS TIME,
EXCEPT FOR THE EYES.
THEY KIND OF STARE BACK AT ME
WHEN I'M SHAVING.
DO YOU FEEL ANY DIFFERENT?
IN A WAY, I FEEL BETTER
THAN I'VE EVER FELT BEFORE
IN MY LIFE.
IT ACTUALLY SEEMS
TO HAVE DONE ME SOME GOOD.
HOW?
WELL, I'M GETTING A CHANCE
TO READ
SOME OF THAT LONGHAIR STUFF
YOU LIKE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HEY, MAN, I REMEMBER YOU
BACK AT THE ACADEMY.
A STACK OF BOOKS WITH LEGS.
THE FIRST THING I EVER HEARD
FROM AN UPPERCLASSMEN WAS,
"WATCH OUT FOR LIEUTENANT KIRK.
IN HIS CLASS,
YOU EITHER THINK OR SINK."
[ CHUCKLES ]
I WASN'T THAT BAD, WAS I?
IF I HADN'T AIMED THAT LITTLE
BLONDE LAB TECHNICIAN AT YOU...
YOU WHAT?
Y-YOU PLANNED THAT?
WELL, YOU WANTED ME TO THINK,
DIDN'T YOU?
I OUTLINED HER WHOLE CAMPAIGN
FOR HER.
I ALMOST MARRIED HER!
YOU BETTER BE GOOD TO ME.
I'M GETTING EVEN BETTER IDEAS
HERE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU? SPINOZA?
ONCE YOU GET INTO HIM,
HE'S RATHER SIMPLE THOUGH.
CHILDISH, ALMOST.
I DON'T AGREE WITH HIM AT ALL.
GO ON.
HEY, I'M TRYING TO TELL YOU
I FEEL FINE.
WHEN DO I GO BACK ON DUTY?
I'M GONNA ASK DR. DEHNER
TO KEEP YOU UNDER OBSERVATION
FOR A WHILE.
WITH ALMOST A HUNDRED WOMEN
ONBOARD,
YOU CAN DO BETTER THAN THAT,
FRIEND CAPTAIN.
CONSIDER IT A CHALLENGE.
THAT DOESN'T SEEM VERY FRIENDLY.
DIDN'T I SAY
YOU'D BETTER BE GOOD TO ME?
[ MUSIC ]
[ CLICKING ]
HE'S READING EVEN FASTER NOW
THAN JUST A FEW MOMENTS AGO.
IS THAT GARY MITCHELL,
THE ONE YOU USED TO KNOW?
PUT A 24-HOUR WATCH
ON THE SICKBAY.
FULLEST POSSIBLE RANGE
OF EXAMINATIONS AND TESTS.
[ MUSIC ]
PERFECT, PERFECT.
I'VE NEVER HAD A PATIENT
LIKE YOU, GARY.
EVEN THE HEALTHIEST
ARE GENERALLY OFF
ON SOME READING.
I KNOW YOU DON'T PARTICULARLY
LIKE ME, MR. MITCHELL,
BUT SINCE I AM ASSIGNED HERE,
CAN WE MAKE THE BEST OF IT?
[ SMIRKS ]
I'VE GOT NOTHING AGAINST YOU,
DOCTOR.
NOR AGAINST THE WALKING
FREEZER UNIT?
WELL, I--SORRY ABOUT THAT.
WOMEN PROFESSIONALS
DO TEND TO OVERCOMPENSATE.
NOW, LET'S TALK ABOUT YOU.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY,
EVERYBODY SEEMS WORRIED
THAT I DON'T HAVE SOME KIND
OF A FEVER OR SOMETHING.
[ SMIRKS ]
MAYBE IF WE COULD JUST CHANGE
THESE DIALS--
NOW, BACK TO NORMAL, I THINK.
HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
I'M NOT SURE, I--
I JUST THOUGHT OF
MAKING IT HAPPEN, AND IT DOES.
IT'S--
HEY--
HEY, WATCH THIS, DOC.
STOP IT. STOP IT!
YOU WERE DEAD
FOR ALMOST 22 SECONDS.
THERE WERE NO READINGS AT ALL.
YEAH.
OH, BOY.
YOU, YOU KNOW, DOC,
THERE HAVE BEEN OTHER THINGS,
TOO, LIKE, LIKE, GOING HALFWAY
THROUGH THE SHIP'S LIBRARY
IN HARDLY A DAY.
YEAH.
OH, WHAT'S HAPPENING TO ME?
DO YOU REMEMBER EVERYTHING
YOU READ THAT QUICKLY?
YEAH.
ON ANY TAPE?
SURE. YEAH.
TRY THIS ONE.
YEAH.
PAGE 387.
"MY LOVE HAS WINGS.
"SLENDER, FEATHERED THINGS
WITH GRACE IN UPSWEPT CURVE
AND TAPERED TIP."
NIGHTINGALE WOMAN,
WRITTEN BY, BY TARBOLDE
ON THE CANOPIUS PLANET
BACK IN 1996.
IT'S FUNNY YOU PICKED THAT ONE,
DOCTOR.
WHY?
THAT'S ONE OF THE MOST
PASSIONATE LOVE SONNETS
OF THE PAST COUPLE OF CENTURIES.
HOW DO YOU FEEL, DOCTOR?
-WHAT?
-HOW DO YOU FEEL?
I JUST FELL. NOTHING HAPPENED.
NO? ARE YOU SURE?
ARE YOU SURE?
I WAS ON MY COFFEE BREAK.
I THOUGHT I'D CHECK UP ON YOU.
YEAH.
THAT'S OKAY, LEE. COME ON IN.
DON'T LET THE LIGHT IN MY EYES
BOTHER YOU, PAL.
IT'S ALL FOR OUR, OUR
GOOD-LOOKING LADY DOCTOR HERE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YEAH. SURE.
SO, UH, SO, HOW GO THE REPAIRS?
WELL, THE MAIN ENGINES ARE GONE,
UNLESS WE CAN FIND SOME WAY
TO RE-ENERGIZE THEM.
YOU'D BETTER CHECK
THE STARBOARD IMPULSE PACKS.
THOSE POINTS HAVE ABOUT DECAYED
TO LEAD.
OH, YEAH, SURE, MITCH.
I'M NOT JOKING, LEE!
YOU ACTIVATE THOSE PACKS,
AND YOU'LL BLOW
THE WHOLE IMPULSE DECK.
I'LL GET ON IT RIGHT AWAY.
I JUST WANTED TO STOP BY
AND MAKE SURE YOU WERE OKAY.
SEE YOU LATER.
HE'S A FOOL.
A FOOL.
HE'D SEEN THOSE POINTS
AND HE HADN'T NOTICED
THEIR CONDITION.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
THE IMAGE OF WHAT HE'D SEEN
WAS STILL IN HIS MIND.
WELL, IT DIDN'T MAKE ANY SENSE
THAT HE'D KNOW,
BUT NATURALLY, I CHECKED OUT
THE CIRCUIT ANYWAY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW,
BUT HE WAS RIGHT.
THIS POINT IS BURNED OUT
EXACTLY THE WAY HE DESCRIBED IT.
SORRY I'M LATE.
I BECAME SO INTERESTED
IN OBSERVING GARY, MR. MITCHELL.
OUR SUBJECT
IS NOT GARY MITCHELL.
OUR CONCERN IS, RATHER,
WHAT HE IS MUTATING INTO.
I KNOW THOSE FROM YOUR PLANET
AREN'T SUPPOSE TO HAVE FEELINGS
LIKE WE DO, MR. SPOCK,
BUT TO TALK THAT WAY ABOUT A MAN
YOU'VE WORKED NEXT TO FOR YEARS
IS WORSE THAN--
THAT'S ENOUGH, DOCTOR.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I UNDERSTAND YOU LEAST OF ALL.
GARY TOLD ME
THAT YOU'VE BEEN FRIENDS
SINCE HE JOINED THE SERVICE,
THAT YOU ASKED FOR HIM ABOARD
YOUR FIRST COMMAND.
IT IS MY DUTY,
WHETHER PLEASANT OR UNPLEASANT,
TO LISTEN TO THE REPORTS,
OBSERVATIONS, EVEN SPECULATIONS,
ON ANY SUBJECT THAT MIGHT AFFECT
THE SAFETY OF THIS VESSEL.
AND IT'S MY SCIENCE OFFICER'S
DUTY TO SEE
THAT I'M PROVIDED WITH THAT.
GO AHEAD, MR. SPOCK.
HAVE YOU NOTED EVIDENCE
OF UNUSUAL POWERS?
HE CAN CONTROL CERTAIN
AUTONOMIC REFLEXES.
HE READS VERY FAST,
RETAINS MORE THAN MOST OF US
MIGHT CONSIDER USUAL.
MR. SCOTT, WOULD YOU REPEAT
WHAT YOU JUST TOLD US?
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO,
THE BRIDGE CONTROLS
STARTED GOIN' CRAZY.
LEVERS SHIFTING BY THEMSELVES,
BUTTONS BEING PUSHED,
INSTRUMENT READINGS CHANGIN'.
AND ON MY MONITOR SCREEN
I COULD SEE MITCHELL SMILING
EACH TIME IT HAPPENED,
AS IF THIS SHIP AND CREW
WERE ALMOST A TOY
FOR HIS AMUSEMENT.
ARE THEY RIGHT, DOCTOR?
HAS HE SHOWN ABILITIES
OF SUCH MAGNITUDE?
I SAW SOME SUCH INDICATIONS.
AND YOU DIDN'T THINK IT
WORTH MENTIONING?
NO ONE'S BEEN HURT, HAVE THEY?
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
A MUTATED SUPERIOR MAN
COULD ALSO BE A WONDERFUL THING.
THE FORERUNNER OF A NEW
AND BETTER KIND OF HUMAN BEING.
MR. SULU.
IF YOU WANT THE MATHEMATICS
OF THIS,
MITCHELL'S ABILITY
IS INCREASING GEOMETRICALLY.
THAT IS LIKE HAVING A PENNY,
DOUBLING IT EVERY DAY.
IN A MONTH,
YOU'LL BE A MILLIONAIRE.
IN LESS TIME THAN THAT,
HE WILL HAVE ATTAINED POWERS
WE CAN'T UNDERSTAND
AND CAN'T COPE WITH.
SOON, WE'LL BE
NOT ONLY USELESS TO HIM,
BUT ACTUALLY AN ANNOYANCE.
THERE'LL BE NO DISCUSSION
OF THIS WITH THE CREW.
THANK YOU.
[ MUSIC ]
WE'LL NEVER REACH AN EARTH BASE
WITH HIM ABOARD, JIM.
YOU HEARD THE MATHEMATICS OF IT.
IN A MONTH, HE'LL HAVE
AS MUCH IN COMMON WITH US
AS WE'D HAVE WITH A SHIP
FULL OF WHITE MICE.
I NEED A RECOMMENDATION, SPOCK,
NOT VAGUE WARNINGS.
RECOMMENDATION ONE,
THERE'S A PLANET
A FEW LIGHT DAYS AWAY FROM HERE:
DELTA VEGA.
IT HAS A LITHIUM
CRACKING STATION.
WE MAY BE ABLE TO ADAPT
SOME OF ITS POWER PACKS
TO OUR ENGINES.
AND IF WE CAN'T?
WE'LL BE TRAPPED IN ORBIT THERE.
WE HAVEN'T ENOUGH POWER
TO BLAST BACK OUT.
IT IS THE ONLY POSSIBLE WAY
TO GET MITCHELL OFF THIS SHIP.
IF YOU MEAN STRAND MITCHELL
THERE, I WON'T DO IT.
THAT STATION IS FULLY AUTOMATED.
THERE'S NOT A SOUL
ON THE WHOLE PLANET.
EVEN THE ORE SHIPS CALL
ONLY ONCE EVERY 20 YEARS.
THEN YOU HAVE ONE OTHER CHOICE.
KILL MITCHELL
WHILE YOU STILL CAN.
GET OUT OF HERE.
IT IS YOUR ONLY OTHER CHOICE,
ASSUMING YOU MAKE IT
WHILE YOU STILL HAVE TIME.
WILL YOU TRY FOR ONE MOMENT
TO FEEL?
AT LEAST ACT LIKE
YOU'VE GOT A HEART.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT GARY.
THE CAPTAIN OF THE VALIANT
PROBABLY FELT THE SAME WAY,
AND HE WAITED TOO LONG
TO MAKE HIS DECISION.
I THINK WE'VE BOTH GUESSED THAT.
SET COURSE FOR DELTA VEGA.
STAR DATE 1313.1.
WE'RE NOW APPROACHING
DELTA VEGA.
COURSE SET FOR A STANDARD ORBIT.
THIS PLANET,
COMPLETELY UNINHABITED,
IS SLIGHTLY SMALLER THAN EARTH.
DESOLATE, BUT RICH
IN CRYSTAL AND MINERALS.
KELSO'S TASK, TRANSPORT DOWN
WITH A REPAIR PARTY,
TRY TO REGENERATE
THE MAIN ENGINES, SAVE THE SHIP.
OUR TASK, TRANSPORT DOWN A MAN
I'VE KNOWN FOR 15 YEARS,
AND IF WE'RE SUCCESSFUL,
MAROON HIM THERE.
I'M THIRSTY.
[ SMIRKS ]
IT'S LIKE A MAN WHO HAS BEEN
BLIND ALL OF HIS LIFE,
SUDDENLY BEING GIVEN SIGHT.
SOMETIMES I FEEL THERE'S
NOTHING I COULDN'T DO, IN TIME.
SOME PEOPLE THINK
THAT MAKES ME A MONSTER,
DON'T THEY, JIM?
ARE YOU READING
ALL OUR THOUGHTS, GARY?
I CAN SENSE
MAINLY WORRY IN YOU, JIM.
SAFETY OF YOUR SHIP.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO IN MY PLACE?
PROBABLY JUST WHAT MR. SPOCK
IS THINKING NOW.
KILL ME WHILE YOU CAN.
[ ELECTRIC BOLTS ]
STOP IT, GARY!
I ALSO KNOW
WE'RE ORBITING DELTA VEGA, JIM.
I CAN'T LET YOU
FORCE ME DOWN THERE.
I MAY NOT WANT TO LEAVE
THIS SHIP, NOT YET.
I MAY WANT ANOTHER PLACE.
I'M NOT SURE YET JUST
WHAT KIND OF A WORLD I CAN USE.
USE?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT ALL YET,
BUT IF I KEEP GROWING,
GETTING STRONGER,
WHY, THE THINGS I COULD DO,
LIKE, LIKE MAYBE A GOD COULD DO.
I WANT HIM UNCONSCIOUS
FOR A WHILE.
[ BEEPING ]
YOU FOOLS!
SOON I'LL SQUASH YOU
LIKE INSECTS.
ENERGIZE.
[ BEEPING ]
CAN YOU DO IT, LEE?
MAYBE IF WE CAN BYPASS
THE FUEL BINS
WITHOUT BLOWING OURSELVES UP.
TAKE HIM.
THERE'S NOT A SOUL
ON THIS PLANET BUT US?
NOBODY BUT US CHICKENS, DOCTOR.
I THINK I GOT THE 203-R SET,
LEE.
GOOD, ALDEN.
TRANSPORT IT UP WITH YOU,
WILL YOU?
OKAY.
THE FUEL BINS, LEE.
COULD THEY BE DETONATED
FROM HERE?
A DESTRUCT SWITCH?
I GUESS I COULD WIRE ONE
UP RIGHT THERE.
DO IT.
HE'S REGAINING CONSCIOUSNESS.
DR. PIPER, I WANT
ONLY ONE MEDICAL OFFICER HERE
AT ANY ONE TIME.
THE OTHER WILL MONITOR HIM
ON THE DISPENSARY SCREEN.
I'D LIKE TO STAY NOW,
TRY TO TALK TO HIM.
MY FRIEND, JAMES KIRK.
REMEMBER THOSE RODENT THINGS
ON DIMORUS?
THE POISONED DARTS THEY THREW?
I TOOK ONE MEANT FOR YOU.
AND ALMOST DIED.
I REMEMBER.
SO WHY BE AFRAID OF ME NOW?
YOU'VE BEEN TESTING YOUR ABILITY
TO TAKE OVER THE ENTERPRISE.
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM,
YOU SAID SOMETHING ABOUT US
SEEMING LIKE INSECTS
BY COMPARISON,
SQUASHING US
IF WE GOT IN YOUR WAY.
I WAS DRUGGED THEN.
YES.
IN THE SICKBAY, YOU SAID
IF YOU WERE IN MY PLACE,
YOU'D KILL A MUTANT
LIKE YOURSELF.
WHY DON'T YOU KILL ME THEN?
MR. SPOCK IS RIGHT
AND YOU'RE A FOOL
IF YOU CAN'T SEE IT.
YOU DON'T MEAN THAT, GARY.
MAN CANNOT SURVIVE OF A RACE
OF TWO ESPERS IS BORN.
IN TIME, YOU'LL UNDERSTAND THAT.
GARY, NO!
JIM.
HIS EYES WENT BACK TO NORMAL.
FIGHTING THE FORCE FIELD
DRAINED HIS STRENGTH,
FOR A WHILE AT LEAST.
HE COULD BE HANDLED NOW.
[ MUSIC ]
I'LL JUST KEEP GETTING STRONGER.
YOU KNOW THAT, DON'T YOU?
IT FITS LIKE A GLOVE, CAPTAIN.
OH, DID MR. SPOCK GET
THE PHASER RIFLE WE SENT DOWN?
I DIDN'T ORDER ANY--
AFFIRMATIVE. LANDING PARTY OUT.
HE TRIED TO GET THROUGH
THE FORCE FIELD AGAIN.
HIS EYES CHANGED BACK FASTER.
HE DIDN'T BECOME AS WEAK.
DR. DEHNER FEELS
HE ISN'T THAT DANGEROUS.
WHAT MAKES YOU RIGHT AND
A TRAINED PSYCHIATRIST WRONG?
BECAUSE SHE FEELS. I DON'T.
ALL I KNOW IS LOGIC.
IN MY OPINION, WE'LL BE LUCKY
IF WE CAN REPAIR THIS SHIP
AND GET AWAY IN TIME.
DIRECT TO THE POWER BINS.
FROM HERE, YOU COULD BLOW UP
THIS WHOLE VALLEY.
IF MITCHELL GETS OUT,
AT YOUR DISCRETION, LEE,
IF SITTING HERE, YOU THINK
YOU'RE THE LAST CHANCE,
I WANT YOU TO HIT THAT BUTTON.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1313.3.
NOTE COMMENDATIONS
ON LIEUTENANT KELSO
AND THE ENGINEERING STAFF.
IN ORBIT ABOVE US,
THE ENGINES OF THE ENTERPRISE
ARE ALMOST FULLY REGENERATED.
BALANCE OF THE LANDING PARTY
IS BEING TRANSPORTED BACK UP.
MITCHELL, WHATEVER HE'S BECOME,
KEEPS CHANGING,
GROWING STRONGER BY THE MINUTE.
HE'S BEEN LIKE THAT
FOR HOURS NOW.
HAVE DR. PIPER MEET US
IN THE CONTROL ROOM WITH KELSO.
WE'LL ALL TRANSPORT UP TOGETHER.
IF HE SHOULD TRY TO STOP US--
KELSO WILL BE
ON THE DESTRUCT BUTTON
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
I THINK HE KNOWS THAT.
I'M STAYING BEHIND WITH HIM.
OUR FISSION CHAMBER THREE
CHECKS OUT.
THE STATION
SEEMS TO BE RUNNING FINE.
YOU'RE A TALENTED THIEF, KELSO.
EVERYTHING YOU SENT UP
SEEMS TO BE FITTIN' IN PLACE.
I'M KINDA PROUD OF THE JOB
WE'VE DONE.
WE'RE GONNA BE READY
TO TRANSPORT UP--
[ GRUNTING ]
[ MUSIC ]
YOU'RE LEAVING WITH THE SHIP,
DOCTOR.
HE IS NOT EVIL.
I GAVE YOU AN ORDER, DOCTOR.
YOU SHOULD HAVE KILLED ME
WHILE YOU COULD, JAMES.
COMMAND AND COMPASSION
IS A FOOL'S MIXTURE.
[ MUSIC ]
IT HIT ME, TOO, WHATEVER IT WAS.
KELSO IS DEAD, STRANGLED.
AT LEAST SPOCK'S ALIVE.
DR. DEHNER?
SHE WENT WITH MITCHELL.
DON'T GIVE HIM A PILL
UNTIL AFTER I'M GONE.
MY FAULT
MITCHELL GOT AS FAR AS HE DID.
DID YOU SEE THEIR DIRECTION?
YES.
THERE WAS SOME MORNING LIGHT.
THEY WERE HEADED
ACROSS THE VALLEY,
TO THE LEFT
OF THE POINTED PEAKS.
THERE'S FLATLANDS BEYOND.
WHEN MR. SPOCK RECOVERS,
YOU'LL BOTH TRANSPORT UP
IMMEDIATELY TO THE ENTERPRISE.
BUT CAPTAIN--
WHERE IF YOU HAVE NOT RECEIVED
A SIGNAL FROM ME
WITHIN 12 HOURS,
YOU'LL PROCEED AT MAXIMUM WARP
TO THE NEAREST EARTH BASE
WITH MY RECOMMENDATION
THIS ENTIRE PLANET BE SUBJECTED
TO A LETHAL CONCENTRATION
OF NEUTRON RADIATION.
NO PROTEST ON THIS, MARK.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
IT'D TAKE ALMOST A MIRACLE
TO SURVIVE HERE.
THEN I SHALL MAKE ONE.
BEHOLD.
[ MUSIC ]
YOU'LL SOON SHARE THIS FEELING,
ELIZABETH.
TO BE LIKE GOD,
TO HAVE THE POWER
TO MAKE THE WORLD
ANYTHING YOU WANT IT TO BE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
A VISITOR.
A VERY FOOLISH MAN.
YOU'LL ENJOY BEING A GOD,
ELIZABETH.
BLASPHEMY? NO.
LET THERE BE FOOD.
KAFERIAN APPLES.
WHENEVER WE VISITED THAT PLANET,
I ALWAYS FAVORED THESE.
CAN YOU HEAR ME, JAMES?
YOU CANNOT SEE ME.
I'M NOT THERE.
YOU FOLLOW THE RIGHT PATH,
JAMES.
YOU'LL COME TO ME SOON.
I CAN SEE HIM IN MY MIND, TOO.
THEN GO TO HIM, ELIZABETH.
AND TALK TO HIM.
NOW THAT YOU'RE CHANGING,
I WANT YOU TO SEE
JUST HOW UNIMPORTANT THEY ARE.
YES, IT JUST TOOK
A LITTLE LONGER
FOR IT TO HAPPEN TO ME.
YOU MUST HELP ME
BEFORE IT GOES TOO FAR.
WHAT HE'S DOING IS RIGHT
FOR HIM AND ME.
AND FOR HUMANITY?
-YOU'RE STILL HUMAN AT LEAST--
-NO.
--PARTLY, YOU ARE.
YOU WOULDN'T BE HERE
TALKING TO ME.
EARTH IS REALLY UNIMPORTANT.
BEFORE LONG, WE'LL BE WHERE
IT WOULD HAVE TAKEN MANKIND
MILLIONS OF YEARS OF LEARNING
TO REACH.
AND WHAT WILL MITCHELL LEARN
IN GETTING THERE?
WILL HE KNOW WHAT TO DO
WITH HIS POWER?
WILL HE ACQUIRE THE WISDOM?
PLEASE GO BACK
WHILE YOU STILL CAN.
DID YOU HEAR HIM JOKE
ABOUT COMPASSION?
ABOVE ALL ELSE,
A GOD NEEDS COMPASSION.
MITCHELL!
ELIZABETH.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT GODS?
THEN LET'S TALK ABOUT HUMANS.
ABOUT OUR FRAILTIES.
AS POWERFUL AS HE GETS,
HE'LL STILL HAVE ALL THAT
INSIDE OF HIM.
GO BACK.
YOU WERE A PSYCHIATRIST ONCE.
YOU KNOW THE UGLY, SAVAGE THINGS
WE ALL KEEP BURIED
THAT NONE OF US DARE EXPOSE.
BUT HE'LL DARE.
WHO'S TO STOP HIM?
HE DOESN'T NEED TO CARE.
BE A PSYCHIATRIST
FOR ONE MINUTE LONGER.
WHAT DO YOU SEE HAPPENING
TO HIM?
WHAT'S YOUR PROGNOSIS, DOCTOR?
HE'S COMING.
THEN WATCH HIM.
HANG ON TO BEING A HUMAN
FOR ONE MINUTE LONGER.
I'M DISAPPOINTED IN YOU,
ELIZABETH.
I'VE BEEN CONTEMPLATING
THE DEATH OF AN OLD FRIEND.
HE DESERVES A DESCENT BURIAL,
AT LEAST.
STOP IT, GARY.
MORALS ARE FOR MEN, NOT GODS.
A GOD, BUT STILL DRIVEN
BY HUMAN FRAILTY.
YOU LIKE WHAT YOU SEE?
TIME TO PRAY, CAPTAIN.
PRAY TO ME.
TO YOU? NOT TO BOTH OF YOU?
PRAY THAT YOU DIE EASILY.
[ GRUNTS ]
THERE'LL ONLY BE ONE OF YOU
IN THE END.
ONE JEALOUS GOD,
IF ALL THIS MAKES A GOD.
OR IS IT MAKING YOU
SOMETHING ELSE?
YOUR LAST CHANCE, KIRK.
DO YOU LIKE WHAT YOU SEE?
ABSOLUTE POWER CORRUPTING
ABSOLUTELY.
[ ELECTRIC BOLTS FIRING ]
HURRY, YOU HAVEN'T MUCH TIME.
GARY, FORGIVE ME.
FOR A MOMENT, JAMES,
BUT YOUR MOMENT IS FADING.
I'M SORRY.
YOU CAN'T KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE ALMOST A GOD.
ENTERPRISE FROM CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1313.8.
ADD TO OFFICIAL LOSSES,
DR. ELIZABETH DEHNER.
BE IT NOTED SHE GAVE HER LIFE
IN PERFORMANCE OF HER DUTY.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
GARY MITCHELL, SAME NOTATION.
I WANT HIS SERVICE RECORD
TO END THAT WAY.
HE DIDN'T ASK
FOR WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
I FELT FOR HIM, TOO.
I BELIEVE THERE'S SOME HOPE
FOR YOU AFTER ALL, MR. SPOCK.
[ MUSIC ]