[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
OUR POSITION, ORBITING PSI 2000,
AN ANCIENT WORLD,
NOW A FROZEN WASTELAND,
ABOUT TO RIP APART
IN ITS DEATH THROES.
OUR MISSION, PICK UP
A SCIENTIFIC PARTY BELOW,
OBSERVE THE DISINTEGRATION
OF THE PLANET.
CHECK OUT
THE LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
RIGHT, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
ALL LIFE SYSTEMS WERE OFF, SIR.
SOMEONE STRANGLED THIS WOMAN.
THE OTHER FOUR ARE BACK THERE.
DEAD?
RIGHT, SIR.
ENGINEER AT HIS POST?
HE'S FROZEN THERE
LIKE HE DIDN'T CARE.
THE REST?
WELL, BETTER LOOK FOR YOURSELF,
MR. SPOCK.
ONE MAN WAS TAKING A SHOWER
FULLY CLOTHED.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BUZZING ]
BE CERTAIN WE EXPOSE OURSELVES
TO NOTHING.
[ BEEPING ]
SPOCK HERE.
DO YOU READ, ENTERPRISE?
Kirk, affirmative.
ALL STATION PERSONNEL ARE DEAD.
What caused it?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
WE'VE DEALT WITH BEFORE.
[ MUSIC ]
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
IT'S FIVE-YEAR MISSION:
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG: STARDATE 1704.2.
THE SCIENCE PARTY
WE WERE TO HAVE PICKED UP
HAS BEEN FOUND DEAD.
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS
HAD BEEN TURNED OFF.
STATION PERSONNEL,
FROZEN TO DEATH.
CONDITIONS HIGHLY UNUSUAL.
MEANWHILE, WE REMAIN IN ORBIT
TO COMPLETE OUR MISSION,
CLOSE SCIENTIFIC MEASUREMENT
OF THE BREAKUP OF THIS PLANET.
YOU RECEIVED MY SIGNAL,
MR. SCOTT?
YES, SIR.
DECONTAMINATE.
[ BUZZING ]
[ WHISTLE ]
CAPTAIN HERE.
SPOCK AND TORMOLEN ABOARD, SIR.
WE'RE HOLDING THEM
IN THE CHAMBER
FOR DECONTAMINATION.
BETTER HAVE MEDICINE
LOOK THEM OVER, TOO.
TELL MR. SPOCK I'LL MEET HIM
THERE IN 10 MINUTES.
KIRK OUT.
YOU'RE FINE, JOE.
UP AND OUT OF THERE.
MR. SPOCK?
[ FAINT SIREN SOUND ]
[ BEEPING ]
YOUR PULSE IS 242.
YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE
IS PRACTICALLY NONEXISTENT,
ASSUMING YOU CALL THAT GREEN
STUFF IN YOUR VEINS BLOOD.
THE READINGS ARE PERFECTLY
NORMAL FOR ME, DOCTOR,
THANK YOU.
AND AS FOR MY ANATOMY
BEING DIFFERENT FROM YOURS,
I AM DELIGHTED.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN.
HOW ARE THEY?
THEY'RE FINE, JIM.
TERRIBLE, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS TERRIBLE.
THEY WERE JUST SITTING
LIKE THEY DIDN'T CARE.
WHATEVER WAS HAPPENING,
THEY DIDN'T CARE.
I KEEP WONDERING--
YOU KEEP WONDERING
IF MAN WAS MEANT TO BE OUT HERE.
YOU KEEP WONDERING,
YOU KEEP SIGNING ON.
ANY GUESSES, MR. SPOCK?
ANY IDEA OF WHAT HAPPENED
DOWN THERE?
I WISH I COULD SAY, CAPTAIN.
THE CIRCUMSTANCES
WERE QUITE BIZARRE,
HOWEVER OUR RECORD TAPES
MAY SHOW US SOMETHING.
SIX DEAD.
SIX PEOPLE DEAD.
YOU BETTER GET SOME REST.
YES, SIR.
SET UP THOSE TAPES, MR. SPOCK.
WE'LL SEE
IF THE ANSWERS ARE ON THERE.
THE LAB STATUS REPORT, DOCTOR.
OH, THANK YOU, CHRISTINE.
[ MUSIC ]
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
NEXT TAPE, PLEASE.
SPECTRO-ANALYSIS TAPE, SIR.
THANK YOU.
[ FAINT SIREN SOUND ]
ALMOST AS THOUGH
THEY WERE IRRATIONAL, DRUGGED.
AN ENGINEER SITTING THERE
APPARENTLY OBLIVIOUS
TO EVERYTHING.
A WOMAN STRANGLED,
A CREWMAN WITH A PHASER PISTOL
IN HIS HAND.
HE'D USED THE COMPUTER ROOM
AS IF IT WERE AN AMUSEMENT
GALLERY.
AND A FULLY CLOTHED MAN
FROZEN TO DEATH IN A SHOWER.
IF THE IMAGE WASN'T SO UGLY,
IT'D BE LAUGHABLE.
NOT EVEN A THEORY, GENTLEMEN?
DEFINITELY NOT DRUGS
OR INTOXICATION.
THE BIOANALYSIS ON THE TAPES
PROVE THAT CONCLUSIVELY.
IT COULD BE SOME FORM OF SPACE
MADNESS WE'VE NEVER HEARD OF,
BUT IT WOULD HAVE TO
BE CAUSED BY SOMETHING.
OUR SPECTRO-READINGS
SHOWED NO CONTAMINATION,
NO UNUSUAL ELEMENTS PRESENT.
OR AT LEAST NONE
YOUR TRICORDERS COULD REGISTER.
INSTRUMENTS REGISTER
ONLY THOSE THINGS
THEY'RE DESIGNED TO REGISTER.
SPACE STILL CONTAINS
INFINITE UNKNOWNS.
EARTH SCIENCE NEEDS
THE CLOSEST POSSIBLE MEASUREMENT
OF THE BREAKUP OF THIS PLANET.
TO DO THIS,
WE NEED THE ENTERPRISE
IN A CRITICALLY TIGHT ORBIT.
QUESTION:
COULD WHAT HAPPENED DOWN THERE
TO THOSE PEOPLE
CREATE ANY UNUSUAL DANGER
TO THIS VESSEL AND CREW?
WE WILL NEED TOP EFFICIENCY,
CAPTAIN.
IT'LL BE A TRICKY ORBIT.
WHEN THE PLANET BEGINS TO GO,
THERE MAY BE DRASTIC CHANGES
IN GRAVITY, MASS,
MAGNETIC FIELD.
THE PURPOSE OF A BRIEFING,
GENTLEMEN, IS TO GET THE ANSWERS
BASED ON YOUR ABILITIES
AND EXPERIENCE.
IN A CRITICAL ORBIT,
THERE'S NO TIME FOR SURPRISE.
UNLESS YOU PEOPLE ON THE BRIDGE
START TAKING SHOWERS
WITH YOUR CLOTHES ON,
MY ENGINES CAN PULL US
OUT OF ANYTHING.
WE'LL BE WARPING OUT OF ORBIT
WITHIN A HALF SECOND
OF GETTING YOUR COMMAND.
Bridge to Captain.
KIRK HERE.
Scanners report
sudden four-degree shift
in planet magnetic field.
A change in mass also, sir.
IT'S BEGINNING.
UNUSUALLY RAPID SHIFTS.
ON OUR WAY, LIEUTENANT.
I'LL HOLD YOU
TO THAT HALF SECOND, SCOTTY.
[ FAINT SIREN SOUND ]
[ MUSIC ]
FOIL.
IT'S A RAPIER.
A THIN SWORD.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WHAT DO YOU DO WITH IT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH IT?
SELF-DEFENSE?
MAYHEM?
SHISH KEBAB?
YOU PRACTICE.
FOR WHAT?
HI, JOEY.
LAST WEEK, IT WAS BOTANY
HE WAS TRYING TO GET ME
INTERESTED IN.
I WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE COLLECTING LEAVES,
PLANT SPECIMENS.
YOUR ATTITUDE IS ALL WRONG.
FENCING TONES THE MUSCLE,
SHARPENS THE EYE,
IMPROVES THE POSTURE.
YOU TELL HIM, JOEY.
EXPLAIN TO HIM.
HEY, JOEY.
YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
GET OFF ME.
YOU DON'T RANK ME,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE POINTED EARS.
SO JUST GET OFF MY NECK!
WHAT'S WITH HIM?
NOTHING.
[ MUSIC ]
[ WHISTLE ]
Attention.
Engine room on standby alert.
All duty personnel
to the bridge.
Acknowledge.
YOU SURE
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT NOW, JOE?
WE'VE GOT TO LEAVE.
WE'RE ALL A BUNCH OF HYPOCRITES,
STICKING OUR NOSES
INTO SOMETHING
THAT WE'VE GOT NO BUSINESS.
WHAT ARE WE DOING OUT HERE,
ANYWAY?
TAKE IT EASY, JOE.
WE BRING PAIN
AND TROUBLE WITH US,
LEAVE MEN AND WOMEN
STUCK OUT IN FREEZING PLANETS
UNTIL THEY DIE.
WHAT ARE WE DOING
OUT HERE IN SPACE?
GOOD?
WHAT GOOD?
WE'RE POLLUTING IT,
DESTROYING IT.
WE'VE GOT NO BUSINESS
BEING OUT HERE, NO BUSINESS.
-TAKE IT EASY, JOE.
-NOW, CALM DOWN.
IF A MAN WAS SUPPOSED TO FLY,
HE'D HAVE WINGS.
IF HE WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE OUT IN SPACE,
HE WOULDN'T NEED AIR TO BREATHE,
WOULDN'T NEED LIFE
SUPPORT SYSTEMS
TO KEEP HIM
FROM FREEZING TO DEATH.
HEY, JOEY,
PUT THE KNIFE DOWN, HUH?
YOU'RE ALL STEAMED UP, JOE.
WE DON'T BELONG HERE.
IT'S NOT OURS. NOT OURS.
DESTROYING AND WATCHING.
WE DON'T BELONG.
I DON'T BELONG.
SIX PEOPLE DIED DOWN THERE.
WHY DO I DESERVE TO LIVE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING, JOE?
HEY, JOEY, PUT THE KNIFE DOWN.
-DON'T BE A FOOL, JOEY.
-LET GO OF ME.
YOU'RE JUST GETTING IN A SWEAT
ABOUT--
LET GO. LET GO.
LET ME HAVE THE KNIFE.
LET ME GO.
JOEY, DON'T BE A FOOL.
JOEY.
JOEY, GIVE ME THE KNIFE.
[ MUSIC ]
EMERGENCY.
REC ROOM AREA THREE NINE.
WE NEED MEDICS.
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
OUR ORBIT, TIGHTENING.
OUR NEED FOR EFFICIENCY,
CRITICAL.
BUT UNKNOWN TO US, A TOTALLY NEW
AND UNUSUAL DISEASE
HAS BEEN BROUGHT ABOARD.
RELATIVE GRAVITY INCREASING,
SIR.
COMPENSATE, MR. RILEY.
YES, SIR.
MAGNETIC FIELD
CONTINUING TO SHIFT, SIR.
PLANET CONTINUING TO SHRINK
IN MASS.
MR. SPOCK?
ALL SCANNING STATIONS MANNED,
ALL RECORDERS FUNCTIONING,
CAPTAIN.
ORBIT STEADY NOW, SIR.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS PLANET
IS CONDENSING
MORE RAPIDLY THAN EXPECTED.
A VALUABLE STUDY.
WE MAY BE SEEING
EARTH'S DISTANT FUTURE.
BEFORE ITS SUN WENT DARK,
THIS PLANET
WAS REMARKABLY SIMILAR TO YOURS.
HELM ANSWERING NICELY, CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
COMMUNICATION STATUS, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
TORMOLEN'S RECORD?
PSYCHIATRIC FILE
AND PERSONALITY QUOTIENTS.
WAS HE TRYING TO KILL HIMSELF?
IT'S DOUBTFUL HE MEANT TO.
HE WAS CONFUSED, SELF-TORTURED.
DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE THE MAN I KNOW.
HIS CAPACITY FOR SELF-DOUBT
HAS ALWAYS BEEN RATHER HIGH.
WHAT PUZZLES ME IS
WHAT BROUGHT IT TO THE SURFACE
WITH SO MUCH FORCE.
[ BREATHING ]
HIS BREATHING RATE IS DROPPING,
DOCTOR.
COMPENSATE WITH THE RESPIRATOR.
[ RESPIRATOR SOUND ]
STAND BY TO CLOSE.
CLOSING.
[ ALARM ]
WHAT IS IT?
RELATIVE GRAVITY INCREASE,
SIR.
LIKE THE PLANET REACHED OUT
AND YANKED AT US.
COMPENSATE.
ORBIT STEADY NOW, SIR.
IT MADE ME A LITTLE NERVOUS,
I GUESS.
THIS SHOULDN'T BE HAPPENING.
THIS MAN
SHOULD BE GETTING STRONGER.
ARE YOU SURE THE RESPIRATOR'S
FUNCTIONING PROPERLY?
YES, DOCTOR.
THEN WHY IS THIS MAN DYING?
HYPO.
[ BREATHING ]
HE'S DEAD, DOCTOR.
THE WOUNDS WERE NOT THAT SEVERE.
[ WHISTLE ]
This is McCoy.
Captain Kirk to sick bay.
UHURA, MONITOR COMMUNICATIONS.
TELL McCOY I'LL BE THERE
WHEN I CAN.
YES, SIR.
PLANET BREAK UP IS IMMINENT,
CAPTAIN,
SHRINKING IN SIZE
AT AN INCREASING RATE.
AS THE PLANET CONTINUES
TO SHRINK IN SIZE,
ITS SURFACE MOVES AWAY FROM US.
FORCING US TO SPIRAL DOWN
TO MAINTAIN
THE SAME DISTANCE FROM IT.
EXACTLY.
WE MUST BE PREPARED TO RESPOND
INSTANTLY TO ANY SUDDEN CHANGE.
ENGINE ROOM FROM BRIDGE.
Scott here, Captain.
TIE INTO THE HELM, SCOTTY.
IF WE SHOULD CALL FOR POWER,
WE'LL WANT IT FAST.
No problem, sir.
You'll have it.
RATE OF COMPACTION
SEEMS CONSTANT.
THEN, I'LL GO SEE
WHAT THE GOOD DOCTOR WANTS.
KEEP ME INFORMED OF ANY CHANGE,
MR. SPOCK.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
DON'T KNOW IF IT'S THIS PLANET
OR WHAT HAPPENED WITH JOE.
I'M SWEATING LIKE A BRIDEGROOM.
YEAH, ME, TOO.
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
HEY, WHY DON'T YOU COME DOWN
TO THE GYM WITH ME,
KEVIN, M'LAD?
NOW?
WHY NOT?
LIGHT WORKOUT
WILL TAKE THE EDGE OFF.
HEY, SULU, WHAT ABOUT--
HEY, SULU, DON'T BE A FOOL.
COME.
INTESTINAL DAMAGE
WASN'T THAT SEVERE.
I GOT TO HIM IN PLENTY OF TIME.
THAT MAN SHOULD STILL BE ALIVE.
ONLY REASON HE DIED, JIM,
IS HE DIDN'T WANT TO LIVE.
HE GAVE UP.
THAT'S A SUPPOSITION, DOCTOR,
NOT A FACT.
WELL, IT MAY BE.
IT MAY BE.
I'VE LOST PATIENTS BEFORE,
BUT NOT LIKE THAT.
NOT JOE'S KIND.
THAT KIND OF MAN
DOESN'T GIVE UP.
COINCIDENCE?
MAYBE.
YOU MEAN THAT JOE WAS DOWN
ON THE PLANET SURFACE,
AND YOU'RE GONNA ASK ME
IF IT'S CONNECTED.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I WAS GONNA ASK.
JIM, HE WAS DECONTAMINATED.
HE'S BEEN MEDICALLY CHECKED.
WE'VE RUN EVERY TEST WE KNOW
FOR EVERYTHING WE KNOW--
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
WELL, WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING
THAT'S POSSIBLE.
BONES, I WANT THE IMPOSSIBLE
CHECKED OUT, TOO.
[ BEEPING ]
WHY ISN'T MR. SULU
AT THIS STATION?
MAGNETIC PULL COMPENSATED FOR,
SIR.
ORBIT STEADY.
TAKE OVER HERE, RAND.
YES, SIR.
YOU HAVEN'T ANSWERED
MY QUESTION.
WHERE IS MR. SULU?
HAVE NO FEAR.
RILEY'S HERE.
AND ONE IRISHMAN
IS WORTH 10,000 OF YOU--
YOU'RE RELIEVED, MR. RILEY.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TAKE OVER THIS STATION.
YES, SIR.
NOW, THAT'S WHAT I LIKE.
LET THE WOMEN WORK, TOO.
UNIVERSAL SUFFERING.
REPORT TO SICK BAY, MR. RILEY.
SICK BAY?
EXACTLY WHERE I WAS HEADED, SIR.
SECURITY, MR. RILEY
IS HEADED FOR SICK BAY.
SEE TO IT HE ARRIVES.
CAPTAIN KIRK TO THE BRIDGE.
WHERE'S JOE?
WELL--
HE DIED, DIDN'T HE?
YES.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
YOU HAVE SUCH LOVELY EYES--
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
--PRETTY LADY.
I KNOW HE WAS A FRIEND OF YOURS.
THIS MUST BE A TERRIBLE SHOCK.
YOU KNOW WHAT JOE'S MISTAKE WAS?
HE WASN'T BORN AN IRISHMAN.
[ MUSIC ]
RICHELIEU, BEWARE!
STAND.
NO FARTHER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
NO ESCAPE FOR YOU.
YOU EITHER LEAVE THIS BOIS
BLOODIED,
OR WITH MY BLOOD ON YOUR SWORDS.
[ LAUGHS MANIACALLY ]
COWARDS!
LIEUTENANT BRENT,
RELIEVE MS. UHURA.
YES, SIR.
WHAT WERE THEIR SYMPTOMS?
NONVIOLENT AT THIS STAGE.
SLIGHTLY DISORIENTED.
RILEY SEEMED RATHER PLEASED
WITH HIMSELF, AS IF HE WERE--
IRRATIONAL OR DRUGGED.
PRECISELY.
SECURITY, LIEUTENANT UHURA.
YES, SIR.
BOTH SULU AND RILEY,
LOCATE AND CONFINE.
I WANT EVERY CREWMAN
WHO COMES IN CONTACT WITH THEM
MEDICALLY CHECKED.
SIR, LEVEL TWO, CORRIDOR THREE
REPORTS A DISTURBANCE:
MR. SULU CHASING CREWMEN
WITH A SWORD.
PUT SECURITY ON IT.
FASCINATING.
A PATTERN IS DEVELOPING.
FIRST, TORMOLEN.
HIDDEN PERSONALITY TRAITS
BEING FORCED TO THE SURFACE.
THEN RILEY, WHO FANCIES HIMSELF
A DESCENDANT OF IRISH KINGS.
AND NOW, SULU,
WHO IS AT HEART A SWASHBUCKLER
OUT OF YOUR 18th CENTURY.
[ BEEPING ]
PRESENT CONDITION OF PSI 2000.
GRAVITY PULL INCREASING.
WE'VE SHIFTED TO 2%
AND SHOULD STABILIZE
OUR POSITION.
HELMSMAN, STABILIZE POSITION.
HELM IS NOT ANSWERING
TO CONTROL.
WARP US OUT OF HERE.
NO RESPONSE FROM ENGINES, SIR.
IMPULSE POWER THEN.
BLAST US OUT OF THIS ORBIT.
IMPULSE ENGINES ALSO DEAD, SIR.
ENGINE ROOM, WE NEED POWER!
MR. SCOTT, ACKNOWLEDGE.
OUR CONTROLS ARE DEAD.
TAKE HER.
RICHELIEU, AT LAST.
SULU, PUT THAT--
PUT THAT THING AWAY.
FOR HONOR, QUEEN, AND FRANCE!
[ LAUGHS ]
[ SWISHING ]
SULU.
AH.
SULU, GIVE ME THAT.
I'LL PROTECT YOU, FAIR MAIDEN.
SORRY, NEITHER.
FOUL RICHELIEU.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO TEACH ME THAT SOMETIME.
TAKE D'ARTAGNON HERE TO SICKBAY.
SCOTTY, WE NEED POWER.
ENGINE ROOM, ACKNOWLEDGE!
You rang, sir?
WHO'S THIS?
THIS IS CAPTAIN KEVIN
THOMAS RILEY
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
And who is this?
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
GET OUT OF THE ENGINE ROOM,
NAVIGATOR.
WHERE'S MR. SCOTT?
I've relieved
Mr. Scott of his duties.
Now, attention cooks.
This is your captain speaking.
I would like double
portions of ice cream
for the entire crew.
CLEAR THAT TUBE, WILL YOU?
YES, SIR.
And now,
your captain will render
an ancient Irish favorite.
♪ I'll take you home
again Kathleen... ♪
CAPTAIN, AT OUR PRESENT
RATE OF DESCENT,
WE HAVE LESS THAN 20 MINUTES
BEFORE WE ENTER
PLANET ATMOSPHERE.
AND BURN UP. I KNOW, MR. SPOCK.
♪ Wild and wide
to where your heart... ♪
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 1704.4.
SHIP OUT OF CONTROL,
SPIRALING DOWN
TOWARDS PLANET PSI 2000.
WE HAVE 19 MINUTES OF LIFE LEFT
WITHOUT ENGINE POWER
OR HELM CONTROL.
HOW DID RILEY GET IN THERE?
HE RAN IN, SAID YOU WANTED US
ON THE BRIDGE.
HE'S CUT OFF
BOTH HELM AND POWER.
AND HE SHUT THE DOOR BEHIND US
AND LOCKED OFF THE MECHANISM.
CAN'T YOU GET
TO THE AUXILIARY?
I CAN'T.
HE'S HOOKED EVERYTHING
THROUGH THE MAIN PANEL IN THERE.
GET UP TO MY OFFICE
AND PULL THE PLANS
FOR THIS BULKHEAD.
THE ONLY WAY
TO GET THAT DOOR OPEN
IS TO CUT THROUGH
THESE WALL CIRCUITS HERE.
♪ THE ROSES
ALL HAVE LEFT YOUR CHEEKS ♪
♪ I'VE WATCHED THEM
FADE AWAY AND DIE ♪
STATUS REPORTS, ALL SECTIONS.
MR. SPOCK,
A FIGHT IN THE AFT WARDROOM.
SECURITY REPORTS INCIDENTS
AMONG THE CREWMEN
ARE INCREASING.
GO TO ALERT BAKER TWO.
SEAL OFF MAIN SECTIONS.
ALL DECKS, ALERT SYSTEM B TWO.
REPEAT,
GO TO ALERT CONDITION BAKER TWO.
SEAL OFF ALL MAIN SECTIONS.
STAND BY.
SEAL OFF, CAPTAIN,
IF WE CAN MINIMIZE THE SPREAD
OF WHATEVER THIS IS.
CONTINUE THE ALERT, LIEUTENANT.
I CAN'T, SIR.
HE'S CUT OFF THE ALERT CHANNELS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
YOU'VE INTERRUPTED MY SONG.
I'm sorry, but there'll be
no ice cream for you tonight.
CUT HIM OFF.
I CAN'T, SIR.
THERE'S NO WAY TO DO IT.
Attention, crew.
This is Captain Riley.
There will be a formal dance
in the bowling alley
at 1900 hours tonight.
NO WAY, CAPTAIN.
HE CONTROLS
THE MAIN POWER PANELS.
HE CAN OVERRIDE ANY CHANNEL
FROM DOWN THERE.
17 MINUTES LEFT, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
Sick bay to bridge.
CAN YOU TIE ME IN
TO THE SICK BAY?
I'M GETTING YOU, JIM.
LOOK,
CAN YOU KEEP THIS BEAST LEVEL?
I'VE GOT SULU TRANQUILIZED.
WE'RE RUNNING TESTS ON HIM.
So far there's nothing unusual
in his bloodstream.
Body functions seem normal.
RILEY'S THE IMMEDIATE PROBLEM,
DOCTOR.
IS THERE ANY WAY,
ANYTHING YOU CAN DO
TO SNAP HIM OUT OF IT?
NEGATIVE, UNTIL I CAN GET
A LITTLE FARTHER ON THESE TESTS.
This is Captain Riley.
Crew,
I have some additional orders.
IN THE FUTURE,
ALL FEMALE CREW MEMBERS
WILL WEAR THEIR HAIR LOOSELY,
ABOUT THEIR SHOULDERS.
And use restraint
in putting on your makeup.
Women,
women should not look made up.
And now, crew,
I will render Kathleen,
one more time!
PLEASE, NOT AGAIN.
♪ I'LL TAKE YOU HOME AGAIN,
KATHLEEN... ♪
♪ I'VE WATCHED THEM
FADE AWAY AND DIE ♪
I'VE SET THE JUMPERS UP THERE.
STANDBY
TILL I GIVE YOU A SIGNAL.
♪ AND TEARS BEDIM
YOUR LOVING EYES, OH ♪
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
TRY YOUR HELM.
YOU'LL HAVE ENOUGH POWER
TO KEEP HER STABILIZED.
HERE, LET'S HAVE A LOOK AT THAT.
[ BEEPING ]
16 MINUTES LEFT, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE STABILIZED,
BUT STILL SPIRALING DOWN.
EMERGENCY SIGNAL, CAPTAIN.
BOTH DECKS FOUR AND FIVE.
FIGHTS AND DISORDERS.
GET ME SICK BAY.
I HAVE NO INTERCOM FOR SICK BAY.
HE KEEPS SWITCHING
CHANNELS ON ME.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN DO
TO HELP DOCTOR McCOY.
BETTER CHECK SCOTTY FIRST.
MOVE HIM FASTER.
HE'S GOT TO GET THROUGH
THAT BULKHEAD.
[ LAUGHS MANIACALLY ]
CREWMAN, REPORT TO THE LAB!
♪ I'LL TAKE YOU HOME AGAIN,
JAN... ♪
WHAT'S GOING ON?
MR. SPOCK,
I'M TRYING TO GET TO THE BRIDGE
AND THIS CREWMAN
WON'T LET ME BY.
CREWMAN, STAND ASIDE.
OH, YES, SIR.
♪ I'LL TAKE YOU HOME AGAIN,
JANICE ♪
SPOCK!
MESSAGE FROM THE CAPTAIN.
TELL HIM I'M DOING MY BEST.
IF I CUT
THROUGH THE WRONG CIRCUITS--
WE HAVE 14 MINUTES LEFT.
EVEN IF WE ARE
UNDER A FULL-SCALE ATTACK,
I COULDN'T MOVE ANY FASTER,
NOT AND MAINTAIN
A SAFETY FACTOR.
AT THE RATE YOU'RE PROCEEDING,
CALCULATIONS SHOW
THAT YOU'LL TAKE
A MINUTE AND A HALF
MORE THAN WE HAVE LEFT.
YOU CAN'T AFFORD
A SAFETY FACTOR.
[ MUSIC ]
BIOPSY LAB.
BIOPSY, WHERE'S MY REPORT?
BIOPSY, COME IN.
HARRISON, WHERE'S MY REPORT?
I'M GOING TO THE LAB.
SIR?
YEAH?
THE TRANQUILIZER'S WEARING OFF.
OH, GOOD.
I'LL NEED HIM CONSCIOUS NOW.
CONTINUE TO EXAMINE HIM
ON CIRCUITS K ONE AND THREE.
OF COURSE, DOCTOR.
[ GRUNTING ]
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
[ LAUGHS ]
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
♪ I'll take you-- ♪
I WOULD'VE GOTTEN HERE SOONER,
SIR.
BUT CREWMAN MOODY STOPPED ME
IN THE HALL--
- TAKE THE HELM.
- SIR?
- YES, SIR.
And now, crew, one more time--
PLEASE TRY AND CUT HIM OFF.
SIR, IF I COULD CUT HIM OFF,
DON'T YOU THINK I--
♪ I'll take you home again,
Kathleen-- ♪
YES, SIR. I'LL KEEP TRYING.
SORRY.
♪ Across the ocean
wild and wide ♪
- SCOTTY?
- Engine room.
WE'VE GOT 12 MINUTES LEFT.
IT'LL TAKE AT LEAST
TWO OR THREE OF THEM
TO GET THE ENGINES
UP TO POWER NOW.
Then we'll make it, sir,
if all goes right.
CALL ME WHEN YOU'VE CUT THROUGH.
I WANT TO BE THERE.
KIRK OUT.
[ MUSIC ]
NURSE?
WHERE IS DR. McCOY?
HE'S GONE TO THE LAB.
LAB?
LAB, RESPOND, PLEASE.
SPOCK HERE.
LAB?
MR. SPOCK?
WHAT IS IT, NURSE?
MR. SPOCK.
[ RATTLING SOUND ]
THE MEN FROM VULCAN
TREAT THEIR WOMEN STRANGELY.
AT LEAST, PEOPLE SAY THAT.
BUT YOU'RE PART HUMAN, TOO.
I KNOW YOU DON'T.
YOU COULDN'T HURT ME.
WOULD YOU?
I'M IN LOVE WITH YOU, MR. SPOCK.
YOU, THE HUMAN MR. SPOCK,
THE VULCAN MR. SPOCK.
NURSE, YOU SHOULD--
CHRISTINE, PLEASE.
I SEE THINGS,
HOW HONEST YOU ARE.
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL.
YOU HIDE IT,
BUT YOU DO HAVE FEELING.
OH, HOW WE MUST HURT YOU,
TORTURE YOU.
I'M IN CONTROL OF MY EMOTIONS.
THE OTHERS BELIEVE THAT.
I DON'T.
I LOVE YOU.
I DON'T KNOW WHY,
BUT I LOVE YOU.
I DO LOVE YOU JUST AS YOU ARE.
OH, I LOVE YOU.
I'M SORRY--
Captain is en route engineering,
Mr. Spock.
Can you take the bridge?
Acknowledge.
I AM SORRY.
CHRISTINE.
[ WHISTLING ]
Bridge to sick bay.
Is Mr. Spock there?
[ WHISTLING ]
Mr. Spock,
would you please acknowledge?
♪ I will take you home,
Kathleen ♪
ALMOST READY, SIR.
♪ To where your heart
will feel no pain ♪
♪ When the fields
are fresh and green ♪
♪ I'll take you to your home-- ♪
READY, SIR?
FOLLOW ME THROUGH.
PUT YOUR PHASERS ON STUN.
DON'T FIRE UNLESS HE'S ARMED.
GO.
[ MUSIC ]
♪ I'LL TAKE-- ♪
NO DANCE TONIGHT.
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
[ BEEPING ]
[ CRYING ]
I'M IN CONTROL OF MY EMOTIONS.
IN CONTROL OF MY EMOTIONS.
I'M AN OFFICER. AN OFFICER.
MY DUTY.
MY DUTY IS--
MY DUTY IS TO--
TOO LATE.
I'M SORRY.
TWO--TWO, FOUR, SIX--
SIX--SIX TIMES--SIX TIMES.
[ CRYING ]
SIX TIMES.
[ BEEPING ]
SCOTTY,
WE HAVEN'T GOT MUCH TIME LEFT.
Bridge to Captain.
KIRK HERE.
Entering
planet's outer atmosphere, sir.
CAPTAIN?
WHAT IS IT?
HE'S TURNED THE ENGINES OFF,
COMPLETELY COLD.
IT'LL TAKE 30 MINUTES
TO REGENERATE THEM.
Ship's outer skin
is beginning to heat, Captain.
Orbit plat shows we have
about eight minutes left.
SCOTTY?
I CAN'T CHANGE
THE LAWS OF PHYSICS.
I GOT TO HAVE 30 MINUTES.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE ENTERPRISE
SPIRALING DOWN OUT OF CONTROL.
SHIP'S OUTER SKIN
HEATING RAPIDLY
DUE TO FRICTION
WITH PLANET ATMOSPHERE.
MAYBE 22, 23 MINUTES--
SCOTTY, WE'VE GOT SIX.
CAPTAIN, YOU CAN'T MIX
MATTER AND ANTIMATTER COLD.
WE'D GO UP
IN THE BIGGEST EXPLOSION SINCE--
WE CAN BALANCE OUR ENGINES
INTO A CONTROLLED IMPLOSION.
THAT'S ONLY A THEORY.
IT'S NEVER BEEN DONE.
BRIDGE,
HAVE YOU FOUND MR. SPOCK YET?
IF YOU WANTED A CHANCE,
ODDS OF 10 THOUSAND TO 1,
MAYBE, ASSUMING
WE HAD A ROW OF COMPUTERS
WORKING WEEKS
ON THE RIGHT FORMULA.
Mr. Spock is not on the bridge,
Captain.
[ SCREAMING ]
I WAS ON THE BRIDGE.
HEY, DOC, WHAT AM I DOING HERE?
McCOY TO BIO. WE'VE ISOLATED IT.
START PREPARING SERUM.
What, Doctor?
[ LAUGHS ]
IT'S WATER.
SOMEHOW ON THIS PLANET,
WATER'S CHANGED
TO A COMPLEX CHAIN OF MOLECULES.
What's that, Doctor?
THAT'S HOW WE MISSED IT.
IT PASSED FROM MAN TO MAN
THROUGH PERSPIRATION.
ONCE IN THE BLOODSTREAM,
IT ACTS LIKE ALCOHOL,
DEPRESSES
THE CENTERS OF JUDGMENT,
SELF-CONTROL.
NOW, GET SOMEONE TO THE LAB.
TELL THEM THE SERUM WORKS,
AND START PREPARING MORE.
[ LAUGHS ]
DOC,
WILL YOU LET ME OUT OF HERE?
-I'M ALL RIGHT.
-[ SNAPPING ]
RELEASE HIM.
[ WHISTLING ]
Engineers, man your stations.
Engine rooms, report.
Cycling station, report.
This will be an emergency
restart of engines.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHAT HAPPENED?
MY MOTHER.
I COULD NEVER TELL HER
I LOVED HER.
WE'VE GOT FOUR MINUTES,
MAYBE FIVE.
AN EARTH WOMAN,
LIVING ON A PLANET
WHERE LOVE, EMOTION,
IS BAD TASTE.
WE'VE GOT TO RISK
A FULL-POWER START.
THE ENGINES WERE SHUT OFF.
NO TIME TO REGENERATE THEM.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
WE'VE GOT TO RISK
A FULL POWER START!
I RESPECTED MY FATHER,
OUR CUSTOMS.
I WAS ASHAMED OF MY EARTH BLOOD.
JIM,
WHEN I FEEL FRIENDSHIP FOR YOU,
I'M ASHAMED.
YOU'VE GOT TO HEAR ME!
WE NEED A FORMULA!
WE'VE GOT TO RISK IMPLOSION!
NEVER BEEN DONE!
UNDERSTAND, JIM?
I'VE SPENT A WHOLE LIFETIME
LEARNING TO HIDE MY FEELINGS.
WE'VE GOT TO RISK IMPLOSION.
IT'S OUR ONLY CHANCE.
IT'S NEVER BEEN DONE.
DON'T TELL ME THAT AGAIN,
SCIENCE OFFICER!
IT'S A THEORY! IT'S POSSIBLE!
WE MAY GO UP
INTO THE BIGGEST BALL OF FIRE
SINCE THE LAST SUN
ON THESE PARTS EXPLODED,
BUT WE'VE GOT TO
TAKE THAT 1 IN 10,000 CHANCE!
Bridge to Captain.
Engineer asked, did you find--
YES, I FOUND MR. SPOCK!
I'M TALKING TO MR. SPOCK,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
Yes, sir.
Three and a half minutes left,
Captain.
I'VE GOT IT, THE DISEASE.
LOVE.
YOU'RE BETTER OFF WITHOUT IT,
AND I'M BETTER OFF WITHOUT MINE.
THIS VESSEL,
I GIVE, SHE TAKES.
SHE WON'T PERMIT ME MY LIFE.
I'VE GOT TO LIVE HERS.
JIM.
I HAVE A BEAUTIFUL YEOMAN.
HAVE YOU NOTICED HER, MR. SPOCK?
YOU'RE ALLOWED TO NOTICE HER.
THE CAPTAIN'S NOT PERMITTED.
JIM,
THERE IS AN INTERMIX FORMULA.
NOW I KNOW WHY IT'S CALLED SHE.
IT'S NEVER BEEN TESTED.
IT'S A THEORETICAL RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN TIME AND ANTIMATTER.
FLESH WOMAN TO TOUCH, TO HOLD.
A BEACH TO WALK ON.
A FEW DAYS,
NO BRAID ON MY SHOULDER.
CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, HELP.
STAND BY TO INTERMIX.
I'LL CALL THE FORMULAE
IN FROM THE BRIDGE.
Entering upper stratosphere,
Captain.
Skin temperature
now 2,170 degrees.
I'VE GOT TO HANG ON.
TELL THEM.
CLEAR THE CORRIDORS,
THE TURBO LIFT.
HURRY.
NEVER LOSE YOU. NEVER.
BRIDGE.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
ENGINE ROOM.
WE'RE SET.
HYPERBOLIC COURSE.
DIRECTION, SIR?
DIRECTION. DIRECTION.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THE WAY WE CAME.
COURSE LAID IN, SIR.
FUEL TEMPERATURE.
LEVEL.
[ BEEPING ]
NO BEACH TO WALK ON.
SIR?
RAISE ANTIMATTER 840 DEGREES.
THAT'LL TAKE FOUR MINUTES.
WE HAVEN'T THE TIME.
WE'LL HAVE TO RISK IT.
BRIDGE, WE'RE READY.
ENGAGE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, JIM?
ARE YOU?
WE FOUND A CURE.
WE'RE OVER THAT PART OF IT.
OBVIOUSLY, WE WERE SUCCESSFUL.
THE ENGINES IMPLODED.
CAPTAIN, MY VELOCITY GAUGE
IS OFF THE SCALE.
ENGINE POWER
WENT OFF THE SCALE AS WELL.
WE'RE NOW TRAVELING FASTER
THAN IS POSSIBLE
FOR NORMAL SPACE.
CHECK ELAPSED TIME, MR. SULU.
MY CHRONOMETER'S
RUNNING BACKWARDS, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
TIME WARP.
WE'RE GOING BACKWARD IN TIME.
HELM, BEGIN REVERSING POWER.
SLOWLY.
HELM ANSWERING, SIR.
POWER REVERSING.
WE'RE BACK TO NORMAL TIME,
CAPTAIN.
ENGINES AHEAD.
WARP ONE.
WARP ONE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK.
YES, SIR.
THE TIME WARP.
WHAT DID IT DO TO US?
WE'VE REGRESSED IN TIME
71 HOURS.
IT IS NOW 3 DAYS AGO, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE 3 DAYS
TO LIVE OVER AGAIN.
NOT THOSE LAST THREE DAYS.
THIS DOES OPEN SOME
INTRIGUING PROSPECTS, CAPTAIN.
SINCE THE FORMULA WORKED,
WE CAN GO BACK IN TIME
TO ANY PLANET, ANY ERA.
WE MAY RISK IT SOMEDAY,
MR. SPOCK.
RESUME COURSE
TO OUR NEXT DESTINATION,
MR. SULU.
COURSE LAID IN, SIR.
STEADY AS SHE GOES.
[ MUSIC ]