[ MUSIC ]
THAT SHOULD MAKE
A GOOD SPECIMEN.
TEMPERATURE'S
STARTING TO DROP.
YEAH.
AT NIGHT, IT GETS DOWN
TO 120 DEGREES BELOW ZERO.
THAT'S NIPPY.
HEY!
WHAT HAPPENED?
I FELL OFF THAT BANK, SIR.
CUT MY HAND.
LET'S SEE.
GET BACK TO THE SHIP.
REPORT TO THE SICK BAY.
YES, SIR.
[ ELECTRONIC BEEPING ]
GEOLOGICAL TECHNICIAN FISHER,
READY TO BEAM UP.
[ MUSIC ]
ALL RIGHT.
LOCKED ONTO YOU.
[ BEEPING ]
ENERGIZE.
CADJULAR ENGAGEMENT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I TOOK A FLOP.
ONTO WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
SOME KIND OF YELLOW ORE.
MAGNETIC.
DECONTAMINATE THAT UNIFORM.
YES, SIR.
THAT ACTED LIKE A BURNOUT.
[ WHISTLE ]
CAPTAIN KIRK READY TO BEAM UP.
JUST ONE MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
[ WHISTLE ]
IT CHECKS OUT OKAY NOW.
YOU BETTER GO GET A SYNCHRONIC
METER SO WE CAN DOUBLE CHECK.
YES, SIR.
[ WHISTLE ]
ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
LOCKED ONTO YOU.
[ WHISTLE ]
[ BEEPS ]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
JUST A LITTLE DIZZY.
HERE, LET ME GIVE YOU A HAND.
I CAN'T GET THROUGH THERE.
NOTHING SERIOUS.
DON'T LEAVE THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM UNATTENDED.
WILSON WILL BE RIGHT BACK, SIR.
[ WHISTLE ]
[ BEEPS ]
[ SINISTER MUSIC ]
[ MUSIC ]
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP, ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION,
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS.
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS.
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1672.1.
SPECIMEN GATHERING MISSION
ON PLANET ALPHA 177.
UNKNOWN TO ANY OF US DURING
THIS TIME,
A DUPLICATE OF ME,
SOME STRANGE ALTER EGO,
HAD BEEN CREATED BY THE
TRANSPORTER MALFUNCTION.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT, SIR?
CAN I GIVE YOU A HAND, SIR?
CAPTAIN?
BRIDGE TO ALL DECKS.
SECTION THREE OFFICERS, PLEASE
CHECK COMMUNICATION LINES.
THANK YOU.
UH, IT MIGHT PROFIT YOU
TO LET DR. MC COY
GIVE YOU THE ONCE OVER.
ALL RIGHT, ENGINEER.
I'LL HAVE MY ENGINES LOOKED TO.
SHIP'S MANIFESTS, SIR.
I THINK THEY'RE IN ORDER NOW.
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
I'VE CHECKED--
THAT'S ALL.
YES, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
YOU PICKED A GOOD DAY, FISHER.
BUSINESS HAS BEEN LOUSY.
WHAT DID YOU DO,
TAKE A FALL ON PURPOSE,
SO YOU COULD GET A
LITTLE VACATION?
SAURIAN BRANDY.
UM, BACK TO DUTY STATUS, FISHER.
I HAVE NO SYMPATHY
FOR CLUMSINESS.
YES, SIR.
THE HAND'S MUCH BETTER, SIR.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU, JIM?
I SAID GIVE ME THE BRANDY!
[ MUSIC ]
[ DOOR KNOCK ]
YEAH?
MR. SPOCK.
COME IN.
YES, MR. SPOCK, WHAT IS IT?
IS THERE SOMETHING I CAN
DO FOR YOU, CAPTAIN?
LIKE WHAT?
WELL, DR. MC COY SEEMED TO THINK
THAT I SHOULD CHECK ON YOU.
THAT'S NICE.
COME ON, SPOCK.
I KNOW THAT LOOK. WHAT IS IT?
WELL, OUR GOOD DOCTOR SAID THAT
YOU WERE ACTING LIKE A WILD MAN,
DEMANDED BRANDY.
[ LAUGH ]
OUR GOOD DOCTOR'S BEEN PUTTING
YOU ON AGAIN.
HMM.
WELL, IN THAT CASE,
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE THE
INTRUSION, CAPTAIN,
I'LL GET BACK TO MY WORK.
I'LL TELL HIM YOU WERE
PROPERLY ANNOYED.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT, SCOTTY?
TRANSPORTER BREAKDOWN, SIR.
CONTINUE CIRCUIT TESTING.
WE BEAMED UP THIS ANIMAL.
AND, WELL, LOOK FOR YOURSELF.
IT'S IN THIS SPECIMEN CASE.
YES?
A FEW SECONDS AFTER THEY
SENT THIS ONE UP
THROUGH THE TRANSPORTER,
THAT DUPLICATE APPEARED.
EXCEPT IT'S NOT A DUPLICATE.
IT'S AN OPPOSITE.
TWO OF THE SAME ANIMAL,
BUT DIFFERENT.
ONE GENTLE, THIS.
ONE MEAN AND FIERCE, THAT.
SOME KIND OF SAVAGE
FEROCIOUS OPPOSITE.
CAPTAIN, WE DON'T DARE SEND MR.
SULU AND THE LANDING PARTY UP.
IF THIS SHOULD HAPPEN TO A MAN--
OH, MY.
[ MUSIC ]
OH, CAPTAIN. YOU STARTLED ME.
IS THERE SOMETHING THAT YOU--
CAN I HELP YOU, CAPTAIN?
JIM WILL DO HERE, JANICE.
OH.
YOU'RE TOO BEAUTIFUL TO IGNORE.
TOO MUCH WOMAN.
WE'VE BOTH BEEN PRETENDING
TOO LONG.
-STOP PRETENDING--
-[ SCREAM ]
LET'S STOP PRETENDING.
COME HERE, JANICE.
DON'T FIGHT ME.
DON'T FIGHT ME, JANICE.
CAPTAIN!
JUST A MINUTE, JANICE.
JUST A MINUTE!
NO! NO!
AAH.
[ SCREAMING ]
CALL MR. SPOCK! CALL MR. SPOCK!
GEOLOGICAL TECHNICIAN FISHER.
DECK 12, SECTION--
ME?  MY YEOMAN SAID THAT?
I'VE BEEN RESTING HERE
SINCE YOU LEFT ME.
ALONE, MR. SPOCK.
CAPTAIN, DR. MC COY REPORTS
THAT YOU DEMANDED THIS BRANDY
IN SICK BAY AND LEFT WITH IT.
I FOUND THIS BOTTLE IN YEOMAN
RAND'S QUARTERS.
NOT TRUE.
I HAVEN'T BEEN TO THE SICK BAY.
LET'S FIND OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
SICK BAY.
[ MUSIC ]
THEN HE KISSED ME.
AND HE SAID THAT WE--
THAT HE WAS THE CAPTAIN.
AND HE COULD ORDER ME.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
AND YOU MENTIONED THE FEELINGS
WE'VE BEEN HIDING.
AND YOU STARTED
TALKING ABOUT US--
US?
WELL, HE IS THE CAPTAIN.
I COULDN'T JUST--
YOU STARTED HURTING ME.
I HAD TO FIGHT YOU AND
SCRATCH YOUR FACE.
YEOMAN?
LOOK AT ME.
LOOK AT ME. LOOK AT MY FACE.
ARE THERE ANY SCRATCHES?
I WAS SURE I SCRATCHED YOU.
I WAS FRIGHTENED. MAYBE--
YEOMAN, I WAS IN MY ROOM.
IT WASN'T ME.
SIR, FISHER SAW YOU, TOO.
FISHER--
IF IT HADN'T BEEN--
I CAN UNDERSTAND.
I DON'T WANT TO GET
YOU INTO TROUBLE.
I WOULDN'T HAVE EVEN
MENTIONED IT.
IT WASN'T ME.
IT WAS YOU, SIR.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE SAYING?
YES, SIR.
I KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
BACK TO THAT BED, BUCKO.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
YOU CAN GO NOW, YEOMAN.
THERE'S ONLY ONE LOGICAL ANSWER.
WE HAVE AN IMPOSTER ABOARD.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1672.9.
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
TEMPERATURES ARE BEGINNING
TO DROP.
OUR LANDING PARTY THERE
IN GROWING JEOPARDY.
DUE TO THE MALFUNCTION
OF THE SHIP'S TRANSPORTER,
AN UNEXPLAINED DUPLICATE OF
MYSELF DEFINITELY EXISTS.
HOW DID ALL THIS HAPPEN?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
BUT WHEN FISHER CAME UP,
HIS SUIT WAS COVERED
WITH A SOFT YELLOW ORE.
IT HAD HIGHLY
UNUSUAL PROPERTIES.
IT MAY HAVE CAUSED AN OVERLOAD.
I CAN'T TELL.
NOT YET.
DOES THE TRANSPORTER
WORK AT ALL?
YES, SIR.
BUT WE DON'T DARE BRING UP
THE LANDING PARTY.
THEY MIGHT BE DUPLICATED
LIKE THIS ANIMAL.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE YOU
TO FIND THE TROUBLE?
CAN'T SAY, SIR.
WE JUST CAN'T LEAVE THOSE FOUR
MEN DOWN THERE.
IT'S GETTING DARK. THEY'LL DIE.
THE SURFACE TEMPERATURE OF
THAT PLANET GOES DOWN TO
120 DEGREES BELOW ZERO AT NIGHT.
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING
WE CAN, SIR.
YES, I KNOW, SCOTTY.
ABOUT YOUR DOUBLE, CAPTAIN.
YES. UH--
YES.
WE'LL HAVE TO FIND HIM.
SEARCH PARTIES, MR. SPOCK.
ORGANIZE SEARCH PARTIES.
WE CAN'T TAKE A CHANCE
ON KILLING IT.
WE HAVE NO PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE,
NO WAY OF KNOWING WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN TO YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT. WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT THE MEN WILL HAVE
TO BE ARMED.
THE MEN ARE TO BE ARMED WITH
THE PHASERS LOCKED--
I REPEAT LOCKED--
ON SETTING NUMBER ONE.
THERE CAN'T BE ANY CHANCE
OF HIM BEING KILLED.
HE'S TO BE TAKEN WITHOUT--
IF THE MEN ARE FORCED TO FIRE,
HE CAN'T BE KILLED.
HOW SHOULD WE EXPLAIN
IT TO THEM, CAPTAIN?
THE SEARCH PARTIES ARE
TO CAPTURE YOU?
TELL THEM--
THE SEARCH PARTIES, CAPTAIN?
YES.
I'LL MAKE AN ANNOUNCEMENT
TO THE ENTIRE CREW.
TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED.
IT'S A GOOD CREW.
THEY DESERVE TO KNOW.
CAPTAIN, NO DISRESPECT INTENDED.
BUT YOU MUST SURELY REALIZE
YOU CAN'T ANNOUNCE THE FULL
TRUTH TO THE CREW.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN OF THIS SHIP.
YOU HAVEN'T THE RIGHT
TO BE VULNERABLE
IN THE EYES OF THE CREW.
YOU CAN'T AFFORD THE LUXURY
OF BEING ANYTHING
LESS THAN PERFECT.
IF YOU DO, THEY LOSE FAITH,
AND YOU LOSE COMMAND.
YES. I DO KNOW THAT, MR. SPOCK.
WHAT I DON'T KNOW IS WHY
I FORGOT THAT JUST NOW.
[ MUSIC ]
MR. SPOCK,
IF YOU SEE ME SLIPPING AGAIN,
YOUR ORDERS--
YOUR ORDERS ARE TO TELL ME.
UNDERSTOOD, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1673.1.
SOMETHING HAS HAPPENED TO ME.
SOME HOW IN BEING DUPLICATED,
I HAVE LOST
MY STRENGTH OF WILL.
DECISIONS ARE BECOMING MORE
AND MORE DIFFICULT.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
SPEAKING.
THERE'S AN IMPOSTER
ABOARD THE SHIP.
A MAN WHO LOOKS EXACTLY LIKE ME
AND IS PRETENDING TO BE ME.
THIS MAN IS DANGEROUS.
UTMOST CAUTION
IS TO BE OBSERVED.
ALL CREW MEMBERS ARE
TO ARM THEMSELVES.
THE IMPOSTER MAY BE IDENTIFIED
BY SCRATCHES ON HIS FACE.
REPEAT.
THE IMPOSTER MAY BE IDENTIFIED
BY SCRATCHES ON HIS FACE.
SECTION CHIEFS, ASSIGN
PERSONNEL TO THE SEARCH.
ALL SEARCH PARTIES REPORT
TO MR. SPOCK FOR ASSIGNMENT.
SOMETHING?
ABOUT THE PHASER WEAPONS
TO BE SET FOR STUNNING FORCE
AND LOCKED--
OH, YES.
YES.
ALL HAND PHASERS MUST BE
SET ON BASE CYCLE,
STUNNING FORCE.
THE IMPOSTER IS NOT
TO BE INJURED.
USE MINIMUM FORCE.
REPEAT--
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK!
--THE IMPOSTER IS NOT
TO BE INJURED.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK!
[ MUSIC ]
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
WILSON.
SIR?
WILSON, GIVE ME YOUR PHASER.
YES, SIR.
HOW YOU BEEN?
FINE, SIR.
[ MUSIC ]
HOW'S IT GOING DOWN
THERE, MR. SULU?
IT'S ALREADY TWENTY DEGREES
BELOW ZERO.
CAN'T EXACTLY CALL IT BALMY.
ISN'T THERE ANY WAY
WE CAN HELP THEM?
THERMAL HEATERS WERE
TRANSPORTED DOWN.
THEY DUPLICATED.
THEY WON'T OPERATE.
THEN WE HAVE GOT TO
GET THOSE MEN OUT.
MR. SPOCK?
SPOCK HERE.
TRANSPORTER TECHNICIAN WILSON
FOUND INJURED NEAR THE
CAPTAIN'S CABIN.
HE SAYS THE IMPOSTER
ATTACKED HIM.
CALLED HIM BY NAME,
TOOK HIS HAND PHASER.
UM, ACKNOWLEDGED.
CONTINUE THE SEARCH.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND
HIM BEFORE HE--
BUT HOW?
APPARENTLY, THIS DOUBLE,
HOWEVER DIFFERENT
IN TEMPERAMENT,
HAS YOUR KNOWLEDGE
OF THE SHIP, ITS CREW,
ITS DEVICES.
THIS BEING THE CASE,
PERHAPS WE CAN OUT GUESS HIM BY
DETERMINING HIS NEXT MOVE.
KNOWING HOW THE SHIP
IS LAID OUT,
WHERE WOULD YOU GO TO
ELUDE A MASS SEARCH?
THE LOWER LEVELS,
THE ENGINEERING DECK.
SET AND LOCKED ON BASE
CYCLE TO STUN,
NOT TO KILL.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR PHASER,
CAPTAIN?
DON'T YOU THINK WE OUGHT TO
GET SOME HELP, CAPTAIN?
NO.
I DON'T WANT ANYONE
ELSE TO SEE THE--
CAPTAIN, YOU ORDERED
ME TO TELL YOU.
MR. SPOCK,
IF I'M TO BE THE CAPTAIN,
I'VE GOT TO ACT LIKE ONE.
[ MUSIC ]
YOU CAN'T HURT ME.
YOU CAN'T KILL ME.
YOU CAN'T.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
I'M PART OF YOU.
YOU NEED ME.
I NEED YOU.
I DON'T NEED YOU.
[ SCREAM ]
[ PHASER BLAST ]
HE'LL BE REGAINING
CONSCIOUSNESS SOON.
AND NOT KNOWING WHAT HIS
PHYSICAL STATE IS,
I DON'T THINK I'D DARE GIVE HIM
A TRANQUILIZER OF ANY KIND.
I THINK WE'D BETTER
BIND HIM.
YES. YES. ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
JUDGING FROM MY OBSERVATIONS,
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE RAPIDLY LOSING THE
POWER OF DECISION.
YOU HAVE A POINT, SPOCK?
YES, ALWAYS, DOCTOR.
WE HAVE HERE AN UNUSUAL
OPPORTUNITY TO APPRAISE
THE HUMAN MIND.
OR TO EXAMINE,
IN EARTH TERMS,
THE ROLES OF GOOD AND EVIL
IN A MAN.
HIS NEGATIVE SIDE,
WHICH YOU CALL HOSTILITY,
LUST, VIOLENCE.
AND HIS POSITIVE SIDE,
WHICH EARTH PEOPLE EXPRESS
AS COMPASSION, LOVE,
TENDERNESS.
IT'S THE CAPTAIN'S GUTS
YOU'RE ANALYZING.
ARE YOU AWARE OF THAT, SPOCK?
YES.
AND WHAT IS IT THAT MAKES ONE
MAN AN EXCEPTIONAL LEADER?
WE SEE HERE INDICATIONS THAT IT
IS HIS NEGATIVE SIDE,
WHICH MAKES HIM STRONG.
THAT HIS EVIL SIDE,
IF YOU WILL,
PROPERLY CONTROLLED AND
DISCIPLINED,
IS VITAL TO HIS STRENGTH.
YOUR NEGATIVE SIDE
REMOVED FROM YOU,
THE POWER OF COMMAND
BEGINS TO ELUDE YOU.
WHAT IS YOUR POINT, MR. SPOCK?
IF YOUR POWER OF COMMAND
CONTINUES TO WEAKEN,
YOU'LL SOON BE UNABLE TO
FUNCTION AS CAPTAIN.
YOU MUST BE PREPARED FOR THAT.
YOU HAVE YOUR INTELLECT, JIM.
YOU CAN FIGHT WITH THAT.
FOR HOW LONG?
IF I SEEM INSENSITIVE TO WHAT
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH,
CAPTAIN, UNDERSTAND,
IT'S THE WAY I AM.
[ WHISTLE ]
CAPTAIN KIRK?
KIRK HERE.
MR. SCOTT, SIR,
ON THE LOWER LEVEL
OF THE ENGINEERING DECK.
I FOUND A NEW TROUBLE
WITH THE TRANSPORTER.
THE CASING HAS A WIDE
GAP RIPPED IN IT.
THE MAIN CIRCUITS
HAVE BEEN BURNED THROUGH.
THE ABORT CONTROL CIRCUIT
IS GONE ALL TOGETHER.
[ MUSIC ]
CAN YOU GIVE US
A STATUS REPORT, CAPTAIN?
TEMPERATURE'S STILL DROPPING.
NOW FORTY-ONE
DEGREES BELOW ZERO.
WE'VE LOCATED THE TROUBLE.
IT SHOULDN'T BE MUCH LONGER.
DO YOU THINK YOU MIGHT BE ABLE
TO FIND A LONG ROPE SOMEWHERE
AND LOWER US DOWN
A POT OF HOT COFFEE?
I'LL SEE WHAT WE CAN DO.
RICE WINE WILL DO
IF YOU'RE SHORT ON COFFEE.
ENGINEERING DECK, KIRK HERE.
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
THAT UNIT, SCOTTY,
STATUS REPORT?
THE TRANSPORTER UNIT IONIZER,
NOTHING MUCH LEFT OF IT, SIR.
HOW BAD IS IT?
WE CAN'T REPAIR IT IN
LESS THAN A WEEK.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1673.5.
TRANSPORTER'S STILL INOPERABLE.
MY NEGATIVE SELF IS UNDER
RESTRAINT IN SICK BAY.
MY OWN INDECISIVENESS GROWING.
MY FORCE OF WILL
STEADILY WEAKENING.
ON THE PLANET,
CONDITION CRITICAL.
SURFACE TEMPERATURE
IS SEVENTY-FIVE DEGREES
BELOW ZERO,
STILL DROPPING.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BUZZING ]
I THINK WE OUGHT TO GIVE
ROOM SERVICE ANOTHER CALL.
THAT COFFEE'S TAKING TOO LONG.
[ ELECTRONIC BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE, THIS IS SULU.
KIRK HERE, MR. SULU.
HOT LINE DIRECT TO THE CAPTAIN.
ARE WE THAT FAR GONE?
I GAVE EVERYBODY THE
AFTERNOON OFF.
I'M WATCHING THE STORE.
HOW IS IT DOWN THERE?
OH, LOVELY.
EXCEPT THAT THE FROST
IS BUILDING UP.
WE'RE USING HAND PHASERS
TO HEAT THE ROCKS.
ONE PHASER QUIT ON US,
THREE STILL OPERATING.
ANY POSSIBILITY OF GETTING
US BACK ABOARD BEFORE
THE SKIING SEASON
OPENS DOWN HERE?
THIS IS SPOCK, MR. SULU.
YOU'LL HAVE TO HOLD ON
A LITTLE LONGER.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY.
SURVIVAL PROCEDURES, MR. SULU.
PER YOUR TRAINING PROGRAM,
MR. SPOCK.
[ SCREAMING ]
[ BEEPING ]
WHAT HAPPENED?
APPARENTLY,
THE BODY FUNCTIONING WEAKENED
DURING THE DUPLICATION PROCESS.
A FACT I FAILED TO CONSIDER.
HE'S NOT DYING?
YES, HE IS.
HELP ME.
HOW CAN HE DIE?
HOW CAN I SURVIVE WITHOUT HIM?
I DON'T KNOW, JIM.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
HERE'S MY HAND.
HOLD ON.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID.
I WON'T LET GO.
HOLD ON.
YOU WON'T BE AFRAID
IF YOU USE YOUR MIND AND THINK.
THINK!
YOU CAN DO IT.
THAT'S IT.
JIM, HE IS BACK.
[ MUSIC ]
JIM, YOU CAN USE
THAT BRANDY NOW.
IN FACT, I'LL JOIN YOU.
I HAVE TO TAKE HIM
BACK INSIDE MYSELF.
I CAN'T SURVIVE WITHOUT HIM.
I DON'T WANT TO TAKE HIM BACK.
HE'S LIKE AN ANIMAL.
A THOUGHTLESS BRUTAL ANIMAL.
YET, IT'S ME.
ME.
JIM, YOU'RE NO DIFFERENT
THAN ANYONE ELSE.
WE ALL HAVE OUR DARKER SIDE.
WE NEED IT.
IT'S HALF OF WHAT WE ARE.
IT'S NOT REALLY UGLY.
IT'S HUMAN.
HUMAN?
YES, HUMAN.
PART OF WHAT HE IS MAKES
YOU THE MAN YOU ARE.
GOD FORBID I SHOULD HAVE
TO AGREE WITH SPOCK,
BUT HE WAS RIGHT.
WITHOUT THE NEGATIVE SIDE,
YOU WOULDN'T BE THE CAPTAIN.
YOU COULDN'T BE.
AND YOU KNOW IT.
YOUR STRENGTH OF COMMAND
LIES MOSTLY IN HIM.
WHAT DO I HAVE?
YOU HAVE THE GOODNESS.
NOT ENOUGH.
I HAVE A SHIP TO COMMAND.
THE INTELLIGENCE,
THE LOGIC.
IT APPEARS YOUR HALF
HAS MOST OF THAT.
AND PERHAPS THAT'S WHERE MAN'S
ESSENTIAL COURAGE COMES FROM.
FOR YOU SEE,
HE WAS AFRAID,
AND YOU AREN'T.
[ WHISTLE ]
CAPTAIN KIRK?
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE.
WOULD YOU COME
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM?
WE THINK WE MAY HAVE
FOUND AN ANSWER.
COMING.
[ MUSIC ]
WHAT IS IT?
WE FOUND A WAY TO GET THE
TRANSPORTER WORKING, SIR.
WE'VE ATTACHED TO SOME
BYPASS AND LEADER CIRCUITS
TO COMPENSATE FOR
THE DIFFERENCE.
TIED DIRECTLY INTO THE
IMPULSE ENGINES.
YES.
THERE SHOULDN'T BE MORE
THAN A FIVE-POINT VARIATION
IN THE VELOCITY BALANCE.
I SUGGEST WE SEND
THE ANIMAL THROUGH.
CAPTAIN?
YES.
YES, GO AHEAD.
[ DOG GROWLS FEROCIOUSLY ]
I'LL GRAB HIM BY THE SCRUFF
OF THE NECK AND HOLD HIM AS LONG
AS I CAN.
DON'T HURT HIM.
IT'S PAINLESS AND QUICK.
THE ANIMAL WILL BE UNCONSCIOUS
FOR ONLY A FEW MINUTES.
UH, IF THIS DOESN'T WORK,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
[ BEEPING ]
ENERGIZE.
REVERSE.
[ BEEPING ]
[ MUSIC ]
THE SHOCK OF PUTTING HIM
BACK TOGETHER SEEMS
TO HAVE BEEN TOO MUCH FOR HIM.
HE'S DEAD, JIM.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STAR DATE 1673.1.
ENTRY MADE
BY SECOND OFFICER SPOCK.
CAPTAIN KIRK RETAINS COMMAND
OF THIS VESSEL.
BUT HIS FORCE OF WILL
RAPIDLY FADING.
CONDITION
OF LANDING PARTY CRITICAL.
TRANSPORTER UNIT
STILL UNDER REPAIR.
AUTOPSY IN DEPTH.
HURRY.
I DON'T KNOW.
THE ANIMAL COULD'VE DIED
OF SOME KIND OF SHOCK.
FOR ONCE I AGREE WITH YOU,
DOCTOR.
I SAID COULD HAVE, MR. SPOCK.
WE WON'T KNOW UNTIL
WE GET A FULL POST MORTEM.
NO AUTOPSY IS NECESSARY TO KNOW
THAT THE ANIMAL WAS TERRIFIED,
CONFUSED.
IT WAS SPLIT INTO TWO HALVES
AND SUDDENLY THRUST BACK
TOGETHER AGAIN.
THUS SHOCK,
INDUCED BY BLIND TERROR.
YES. YES.
THAT SOUNDS LIKELY.
IT COULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU CAN.
YOU HAVE YOUR INTELLIGENCE
CONTROLLING YOUR FEAR.
GET THE TRANSPORTER ROOM READY.
COULD BE, IF, MAYBE,
ALL GUESSWORK SO FAR,
JUST THEORY.
JIM, WHY DON'T YOU GIVE ME
A CHANCE TO DO AN AUTOPSY
AND LET SPOCK CHECK OUT THE
TRANSPORTER CIRCUITS AGAIN?
THAT SOUNDS--
SOUNDS REASONABLE.
WE SHOULD DOUBLE CHECK
EVERYTHING.
AREN'T YOU FORGETTING
SOMETHING, CAPTAIN?
NO.
I DON'T THINK I FOR--
YOUR MEN ON THE PLANET SURFACE.
HOW MUCH TIME DO THEY HAVE LEFT?
YES, THAT'S RIGHT, THE MEN.
WE HAVE TO TAKE THE CHANCE,
BONES.
THEIR LIVES--
SUPPOSE IT WASN'T SHOCK, JIM.
SUPPOSE THE DEATH WAS CAUSED
BY A TRANSPORTER MALFUNCTION.
THEN, YOU'D DIE.
THEY'D DIE ANYWAY.
JIM, YOU CAN'T RISK
YOUR LIFE ON A THEORY!
BEING SPLIT IN TWO HALVES
IS NO THEORY WITH ME, DOCTOR.
I HAVE A HUMAN HALF, YOU SEE.
AS WELL AS AN ALIEN
HALF SUBMERGED,
CONSTANTLY AT WAR
WITH EACH OTHER.
PERSONAL EXPERIENCE, DOCTOR.
I SURVIVE IT
BECAUSE MY INTELLIGENCE
WINS OUT OVER BOTH.
IT MAKES THEM LIVE TOGETHER.
YOUR INTELLIGENCE WOULD ENABLE
YOU TO SURVIVE, AS WELL.
WELL, SOMEBODY MAKE A DECISION.
ARE YOU RELINQUISHING
YOUR COMMAND, CAPTAIN?
NO.
NO, I'M NOT.
WELL, THEN, WE CAN'T
HELP YOU, JIM.
THE DECISION IS YOURS.
MR. SPOCK,
READY THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
BONES, CONTINUE THE AUTOPSY.
[ MUSIC ]
[ WHISTLE ]
CAPTAIN KIRK?
I HAVE A TIE-IN WITH SULU, NOW.
KIRK HERE.
[ WIND BLOWING ]
CAPTAIN K-KIRK, SULU HERE.
ONE HUNDRED SEVENTEEN BELOW--
CAN'T LAST MUCH LONGER.
CAN'T SEE CLEARLY, DOCTOR,
TO READ TOP INDICATOR.
THINK THE COLD PENETRATING
COMMUNICATOR.
TWO MEN UNCONSCIOUS.
NO TIME.
NO--
CAN'T WAIT.
NO TIME.
MR. SULU?
CAN'T WAIT.
CAN'T LET THEM DIE.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
GO THROUGH THE TRANSPORTER,
BOTH OF US.
THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO TO STOP YOU?
IT'S WHAT I HAVE TO DO.
IT'S WHAT I HAVE TO DO,
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO.
I WON'T FIGHT YOU ANYMORE.
OH. I FEEL SO WEAK.
I'LL BE GLAD WHEN THIS IS OVER.
[ GRUNT ]
[ MUSIC ]
JANICE, HELLO.
CAPTAIN, UH--
YEOMAN,
I OWE YOU AN EXPLANATION.
NO--
YES, I DO.
THE TRANSPORTER MALFUNCTIONED.
DIVIDED ME.
CREATED A DUPLICATE.
THE ANIMAL PART OF ME
CAME TO YOUR CABIN.
HE EVEN SCRATCHED ME
TO MAKE US LOOK MORE ALIKE.
I'D LIKE THE CHANCE
TO EXPLAIN IT TO YOU.
YOU DON'T MIND
IF I COME TO YOUR CABIN LATER?
NO, SIR.
BRIDGE.
NO WORD FROM MR. SULU, SIR.
PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT,
MR. FARRELL.
WELL?
CAPTAIN!
I GAVE YOU AN ORDER,
MR. FARRELL.
BUT WHAT ABOUT--
THEY CAN'T BE SAVED.
PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT.
YES, SIR.
BUT I THOUGHT WE PLANNED--
I CHANGED MY MIND.
GO BACK TO YOUR STATION,
MR. SPOCK.
GRAB HIM.
HE'S THE IMPOSTER.
NO!
MC COY, HE'S FOOLED YOU.
HE ATTACKED HIM.
MR. SPOCK, YOU KNOW WHO I AM.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
MR. SPOCK, WHICH ONE?
WHAT DO WE DO?
WE'LL LET THE CAPTAIN
HANDLE THIS.
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
ISN'T THAT OBVIOUS?
LOOK AT HIS FACE.
REMEMBER THE SCRATCHES?
LOOK HOW HE'S TRIED
TO HIDE THEM.
HE WANTS YOU TO THINK
THAT HE'S CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU KNOW WHO I AM.
[ MUSIC ]
YES, I KNOW.
YOU WANT TO KILL ME, DON'T YOU?
FARRELL!
JAMES!
GRAB HIM.
HE'LL DESTROY THE SHIP!
I'M THE CAPTAIN!
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
I'M CAPTAIN OF THE SHIP!
I'M THE CAPTAIN!
THIS IS MY SHIP!
MY SHIP!
IT'S MINE!
[ MUSIC ]
I'LL KILL YOU.
CAN HALF A MAN LIVE?
TAKE ANOTHER STEP, YOU'LL DIE.
THEN, WE'LL BOTH DIE.
PLEASE?
I DON'T WANT TO.
DON'T MAKE ME.
I DON'T WANT TO GO BACK.
PLEASE?
I WANT TO LIVE!
YOU WILL.
BOTH OF US.
I WANT TO LIVE!
[ MUSIC ]
YOU'LL HAVE TO HOLD ONTO HIM,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK?
CAPTAIN?
IF THIS DOESN'T WORK--
UNDERSTOOD, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]
MR. SPOCK?
[ BEEPING ]
READY.
WELL, MR. SPOCK?
[ BEEPING ]
JIM?
GET THOSE MEN ABOARD FAST.
RIGHT AWAY, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]
SEVERE EXPOSURE, FROST BITE.
BUT I THINK THEY'LL MAKE IT.
HOW DO YOU FEEL, JIM?
HOW?
I'VE SEEN A PART OF MYSELF
NO MAN SHOULD EVER SEE.
STATUS REPORT, GREEN.
ALL SECTIONS REPORT READY, SIR.
GOOD.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK,
FROM BOTH OF US.
SHALL I PASS THAT ON
TO THE CREW, SIR?
THE IMPOSTER'S BACK
WHERE HE BELONGS.
LET'S FORGET HIM.
CAPTAIN?
THE IMPOSTER TOLD
ME WHAT HAPPENED.
OH?
WHO HE REALLY WAS.
AND I'D JUST LIKE TO SAY THAT--
WELL, SIR,
WHAT I'D LIKE TO SAY IS THAT--
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
[ MUSIC ]
THE, UH,
IMPOSTER HAD SOME INTERESTING
QUALITIES, WOULDN'T YOU SAY,
YEOMAN?
[ MUSIC ]
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
NAVIGATOR,
SET IN COURSE CORRECTION.
HELMSMEN, STEADY AS SHE GOES.
[ MUSIC ]