CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 1329.8.
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
IN PURSUIT
OF AN UNIDENTIFIED VESSEL.
Sulu: THERE HE IS, SIR.
CENTER SCREEN.
STILL TRYING
TO RUN AWAY
FROM US, SIR.
DON'T LOSE HIM,
MR. SULU.
NO, SIR.
EARTH SHIP, MR. SPOCK?
DIFFICULT TO SAY,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE GETTING
NO REGISTRATION BEAM
FROM IT.
IF IT IS, HE'LL SOON
OVERLOAD HIS ENGINES.
Spock: SIR,
HE'S PUSHING HIS ENGINES
TOO HARD.
CHANGING COURSE
AGAIN.
HE KNOWS
WE'RE AFTER HIM
ALL RIGHT.
STAY WITH HIM,
MR. SULU.
COMMUNICATION?
I'VE TRIED ALL
FREQUENCIES, SIR.
HE REFUSES
TO ANSWER,
UNLESS HE'S NOT
RECEIVING US.
OH, HE'S RECEIVING US,
ALL RIGHT.
APPROACHING
AN ASTEROID BELT,
CAPTAIN.
SCHILLER RATING--
3.5.
DEFLECTORS ON,
MR. FARRELL.
HE'S SEEN
THE ASTEROID,
TOO, SIR.
STAY WITH HIM.
HE'LL TRY
TO LOSE US IN THEM.
Sulu: IF ONE OF
THEM HITS HIM--
Spock: SENSOR READING
ON THE VESSEL, CAPTAIN.
I MAKE IT OUT AS A SMALL,
CLASS "J" CARGO SHIP,
AND HIS ENGINES
ARE SUPER-HEATING.
TRY TO WARN HIM.
IF HE LOSES POWER NOW--
Farrell: THERE GO
HIS ENGINES, SIR.
Sulu: HE IS DRIFTING
INTO ASTEROID BELT,
CAPTAIN.
HE'S HAD IT,
UNLESS WE PUT
OUR DEFLECTOR SCREEN
AROUND HIM.
CAPTAIN, IF WE TRY,
WE'LL OVERLOAD
OUR OWN ENGINES.
HE'S TOO FAR AWAY.
COVER HIM WITH
OUR DEFLECTOR SCREEN,
MR. FARRELL.
[WHIRS]
SCOTTY, SPOCK, STAND BY
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AYE, SIR.
WE'RE PROTECTING HIM,
SIR.
WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO HOLD IT LONG.
WE'RE OVERLOADING,
CAPTAIN.
ENGINE TEMPERATURES
CLIMBING.
[BEEPING]
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Man: THIS IS
THE ENGINE ROOM.
TEMPERATURES ARE PASSING
THE DANGER LINE.
OUR DEFLECTOR SCREEN'S
WEAKENING, SIR.
WE CAN'T PROTECT THEM
MUCH LONGER.
[BUZZES]
THAT WAS ONE OF
OUR LITHIUM CRYSTAL
CIRCUITS, SIR.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
IF YOU DON'T START BEAMING
THAT CREW OVER SOON--
Scotty: THEY'RE NOT
ANSWERING OUR SIGNAL.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO LOCK ONTO.
ANOTHER CIRCUIT, SIR.
I'M GETTING
A DISTRESS
SIGNAL CALL
FROM THEM, SIR.
SCOTTY, WE'RE GETTING
A DISTRESS SIGNAL.
[BEEPS]
Scotty: WE'RE LOCKED ONTO
SOMETHING, CAPTAIN.
MEANING NO INGRATITUDE,
GENTLEMEN,
BUT JUST WHERE IS IT
I FIND MESELF?
YOU'RE ABOARD
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
IT'S REALLY
A DARN BEAUTIFUL SHIP,
ISN'T IT?
REALLY A BEAUTIFUL SHIP.
OH, THE NAME, GENTLEMEN,
IS WALSH. CAPTAIN LEO WALSH.
HOW MANY MORE
IN YOUR CREW?
JUST A FEW MORE.
YOUR VESSEL'S
BREAKING UP, MAN.
IF WE DON'T
GET THEM OVER HERE
RIGHT NOW--
WE COULDN'T BE SURE
YOU WAS A FRIENDLY VESSEL,
NOW COULD WE?
AH, BUT THE 3 OF THEM
WILL BE IN POSITION
RIGHT ABOUT BY NOW.
[WHIRS]
[BUZZES]
ANOTHER LITHIUM CIRCUIT.
NOW SUPPLEMENTING
WITH BATTERY POWER, SIR.
SCOTTY, HOW MANY OF THEM
DID YOU GET ABOARD?
ONLY ONE, SIR,
BUT WE'VE LOCKED ONTO
3 MORE.
Kirk: WHAT'S WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
WITH THOSE 3
LITHIUM CRYSTALS GONE--
AT BEST,
IT'LL TAKE LONGER
ON BATTERY POWER.
NEVER DID
TRUST THIS THING
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
THERE SHE GOES!
Sulu: ASTEROID.
HIT HIM DEAD CENTER.
Kirk: BRIDGE
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
THEIR VESSEL HAS BEEN HIT
BY AN ASTEROID. IT'S GONE.
DID YOU GET THE CREW OFF?
NOT YET, SIR,
BUT WE'VE HOOKED
ONTO SOMETHING.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
KIRK TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
REPORT.
Walsh: IT'S ALL RIGHT,
DARLINGS.
WE'RE IN GOOD HANDS.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
WE'RE CLEARING
THE ASTEROID BELT
NOW, CAPTAIN.
DEFLECTOR SCREEN DOWN,
MR. FARRELL. CONSERVE POWER.
CAPTAIN
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
ARE YOU READING ME OR NOT,
MR. SCOTT?
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
HOW MANY
DID WE GET OFF?
OH.
UM...
4 IN ALL, SIR.
IF THE CAPTAIN
OF THAT VESSEL CAN WALK,
I WANT HIM
IN MY CABIN IMMEDIATELY.
CORRECTION--
I WANT HIM THERE
WHETHER HE CAN WALK
OR NOT. KIRK OUT.
THAT FELLOW SOUNDED
A MITE UPSET, DIDN'T HE?
YES.
YES, THEY ARE.
CURIOUS.
YOU'RE CERTAIN THIS WAS
EVERYONE ABOARD, MR. WALSH?
NO OTHER CREWMEN?
OH, NO. THAT'S EVERYONE,
ALL RIGHT.
BUT SO FAR AS THE LADIES
ACTUALLY BEING THE CREW--
YOU CAN EXPLAIN THAT
TO THE CAPTAIN.
AYE!
AMEN TO THAT,
SCOTTY.
Walsh: SURE, THESE
STARSHIPS ARE REALLY
SOMETHING MARVELOUS,
BUT MEN
WILL ALWAYS BE MEN,
NO MATTER
WHERE THEY ARE.
EH, MISTER? YOU'LL NEVER
TAKE THAT OUT OF THEM.
DECK 12.
YOU'RE PART VULCANIAN,
AREN'T YOU?
MMM.
AH, WELL, THEN,
A PRETTY FACE
DOESN'T AFFECT YOU
AT ALL, DOES IT?
THAT IS, NOT UNLESS
YOU WANT IT TO.
YOU CAN SAVE IT, GIRLS.
THIS TYPE
CAN TURN HIMSELF OFF
FROM ANY EMOTION.
[DOOR OPENS]
I APOLOGIZE
FOR WHAT HE SAID, SIR.
HE'S SO USED TO BUYING
AND SELLING PEOPLE.
I'LL HANDLE
THE CONVERSATION, DARLIN'.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
COME.
THE COMMANDER
OF THE TRANSPORT
TO SEE YOU, CAPTAIN.
GOOD. NOW, IF YOU
DON'T MIND TELLING--
HELLO.
AND THE LADIES?
IS THIS YOUR CREW,
CAPTAIN?
Walsh: WELL,
NO, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS ME CARGO.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 1329.1.
WE HAVE TAKEN ABOARD FROM
UNREGISTERED TRANSPORT VESSEL
ITS CAPTAIN AND--
AND 3 UNUSUAL FEMALES.
THESE WOMEN HAVE A MYSTERIOUS,
MAGNETIC EFFECT
ON THE MALE MEMBERS
OF MY CREW,
INCLUDING MYSELF.
EXPLANATION UNKNOWN
AT PRESENT.
WELL, HOW THE DEVIL
AM I SUPPOSED TO KNOW
THIS IS A STARSHIP,
CAPTAIN?
HERE I AM WITH A CARGO
OF YOUNG LOVELIES,
A STRANGE SHIP
COMES UP ALONGSIDE--
WELL, NATURALLY,
I DID ME BEST
TO EVADE YOU.
AND STARSHIP CAPTAIN OR NO,
YOU EXCEEDED YOUR AUTHORITY
WHEN YOU DROVE ME AND MINE
INTO A SHOWER OF ASTEROIDS.
YOUR NAME, PLEASE.
WALSH. LEO WALSH.
YOU DESTROYED
ME SHIP, CAPTAIN.
MR. WALSH, I'M CONVENING
A SHIP'S HEARING
ON YOUR ACTIONS.
MR. SPOCK WILL SUPPLY YOU
WITH ANY LEGAL INFORMATION
YOU MAY NEED
FOR YOUR DEFENSE.
YOU'RE A HARD-NOSED ONE,
CAPTAIN.
AND YOU'RE A LIAR,
MR. WALSH.
I THINK WE BOTH
UNDERSTAND EACH OTHER.
SECURITY!
ESCORT MR. WALSH
TO HIS QUARTERS.
CONFINE HIM THERE.
YOU'RE ON DUTY,
JOHNNY-O.
BACK TO REALITY.
YOU CAN FEEL THEIR EYES
WHEN THEY LOOK AT YOU,
LIKE SOMETHING
GRABBING HOLD OF YOU.
DID YOU NOTICE THAT?
I NOTICED.
HOW I NOTICED!
COME ON,
NOW, JOHNNY. OK.
WE'VE GOT TROUBLE,
MR. SPOCK.
I'M WELL AWARE OF THAT,
MR. SCOTT.
ONE LITHIUM CRYSTAL
LEFT,
AND THAT WITH
A HAIRLINE SPLIT
AT THE BASE.
BETTER RIG
A BY-PASS CIRCUIT.
CAN'T.
WE BLEW THE WHOLE
CONVERTER ASSEMBLY.
[CLICKS]
KIRK HERE.
NEEDED ON THE BRIDGE,
CAPTAIN.
[INDISTINCT WHISPERING]
HARRY!
WHERE WERE YOU?
SHH! CALM DOWN NOW.
WOULD YOU MIND
WAITING OUTSIDE?
SORRY, SIR.
WELL, NOW,
ANSWER EVERY QUESTION
THEY PUT TO YOU.
DON'T LIE.
WELL, YOU'VE NO NEED TO,
HAVE YOU?
AND DON'T SUBMIT
TO A MED--
THAT IS,
BEING SO HEALTHY,
THEY'VE NO NEED
FOR A MEDICAL EXAM,
HAVE THEY?
BUT WHAT IF
THEY ASK ABOUT--
THEY WON'T. HAVE YOU
NO PLACE TO GO, LADS?
THEY'LL NOTICE
WE'RE DIF--
NO, NO, NO,
THEY WON'T.
YOU JUST LET LEO TAKE
ALL THE HARD QUESTIONS.
NOW, DON'T BE PANICKING,
LOVES. WE'LL GET TO--
GET WHERE?
WE DON'T HAVE
A SHIP,
AND WE'RE HEADED
THE WRONG WAY,
HARRY.
LE--
LEO.
LEO WALSH IS ME NAME,
DARLING.
DON'T FORGET THAT.
SO LOVELY.
LOVELY, AREN'T THEY?
IF THEY ONLY THINK
LOVELY THOUGHTS,
IF THEY SMILE,
WHY, THEY'LL COME OUT RIGHT
SOME WHICH WAY,
NOW WON'T THEY?
ME PERSONAL GUARANTEE
ON THAT.
THE ENTIRE SHIP'S POWER
IS FEEDING THROUGH
ONE LITHIUM CRYSTAL.
WELL, SWITCH
TO BY-PASS CIRCUITS.
WE BURNED THEM ALL OUT
WHEN WE SUPER-HEATED,
CAPTAIN.
THAT JACKASS WALSH
NOT ONLY WRECKED
HIS OWN VESSEL,
BUT IN SAVING
HIS SKIN--
IF IT MAKES YOU FEEL
ANY BETTER, ENGINEER,
THAT'S ONE JACKASS
WE'RE GOING TO SEE SKINNED.
BUT IT'S
FRUSTRATING.
ALMOST A MILLION
GROSS TONS OF VESSEL
DEPENDING ON
A HUNK OF CRYSTAL
THE SIZE OF MY FIST.
Spock: AND THAT CRYSTAL
WON'T HOLD UP--
NOT PULLING ALL OUR POWER
THROUGH IT.
WELL,
MR. SPOCK?
THERE'S A LITHIUM
MINING OPERATION
ON RIGEL-12.
HIGH-GRADE ORE,
I'VE HEARD.
LOCATION
AND DISTANCE.
MR. FARRELL
HAS THE COURSE.
LESS THAN
2 DAYS' TRAVEL.
MAKE FOR RIGEL-12,
MR. SPOCK.
Spock: RIGEL-12,
MR. FARRELL.
YOU HAVE THE COURSE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 1329.2.
ON BOARD
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
A SHIP'S HEARING
IS BEING CONVENED
AGAINST
THE TRANSPORT VESSEL'S
CAPTAIN.
I'M BECOMING CONCERNED ABOUT
THE ALMOST HYPNOTIC EFFECT
PRODUCED BY THE WOMEN.
THIS HEARING IS CONVENED.
STARDATE 1329.2,
ON BOARD STARSHIP
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
FORMAL HEARINGS AGAINST
TRANSPORT CAPTAIN LEO WALSH.
START COMPUTER.
STATE YOUR NAME
FOR THE RECORD.
LEO FRANCIS WALSH.
INCORRECT.
YOUR CORRECT NAME.
GENTLEMEN, SURELY
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO TAKE THE WORD
OF A SOULLESS
MECHANICAL DEVICE
OVER THAT OF A REAL,
FLESH-AND-BLOOD MAN.
[SIGHS]
STATE YOUR CORRECT NAME
FOR THE RECORD.
HARRY MUDD.
INCORRECT.
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD.
ANY PAST OFFENSES,
MR. MUDD?
OF COURSE NOT.
GENTLEMEN, I'M SIMPLY
AN HONEST BUSINESSMAN.
INCORRECT.
BLAST THAT
TIN-PLATED POT.
FULL DATA COMING
ON-SCREEN.
IF IT CAN READ
OUR MINDS, TOO...
THEY CAN'T, DARLING.
THEY CAN'T.
JUST WHAT'S
ON THE RECORD.
OFFENSE RECORD--
SMUGGLING.
SENTENCE...SUSPENDED.
TRANSPORT
OF STOLEN GOODS.
PURCHASE OF SPACE VESSEL
WITH COUNTERFEIT CURRENCY.
SENTENCES--
PSYCHIATRIC TREATMENT,
EFFECTIVENESS DISPUTED.
Kirk: MR. MUDD,
YOU ARE CHARGED
WITH GALAXY TRAVEL
WITHOUT A FLIGHT PLAN,
WITHOUT
AN IDENTIFICATION BEAM,
AND FAILURE TO ANSWER
A STARSHIP'S SIGNAL,
THUS EFFECTING
A MENACE TO NAVIGATION.
WHAT, MY TINY, LITTLE SHIP
IN THIS IMMENSE GALAXY
A MENACE TO NAVIGATION?
YOU'RE ALSO CHARGED
WITH OPERATION OF A VESSEL
WITHOUT A MASTER'S LICENSE.
UNTRUE! I HAVE
A MASTER'S TICKET.
INCORRECT.
MASTER'S LICENSE REVOKED
STARDATE 1116.4.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, VERY SIMPLY,
LEO WALSH, WHO WAS TO BE
MY CAPTAIN ON THIS TRIP,
PASSED AWAY SUDDENLY.
WELL, I HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO TAKE OUT ME SHIP
ME OWN SELF, DID I?
WELL, I ASSUMED LEO'S NAME
FOR THIS VOYAGE
OUT OF COURTESY TO HIM.
IN MEMORIAM, AS IT WERE.
A FINE, FINE MAN,
ALAS,
GONE TO HIS REWARD.
DESTINATION AND PURPOSE
OF JOURNEY?
PLANET OPHIUCHUS-3.
WIVING SETTLERS.
COME AGAIN,
MR. MUDD?
YOU DO WHAT?
I RECRUIT WIVES
FOR SETTLERS,
A DIFFICULT
BUT SATISFYING TASK.
DATA ON WITNESSES.
NO DATA.
COMPUTER,
GO TO SENSOR PROBE.
ANY UNUSUAL READINGS?
NO DECIPHERABLE READING
ON FEMALES.
HOWEVER, UNUSUAL READING
ON MALE BOARD MEMBERS.
DETECTING HIGH
RESPIRATION PATTERNS,
PERSPIRATION RATES UP,
HEARTBEAT RAPID,
BLOOD PRESSURE
HIGHER THAN NORMAL.
UH, THAT'S SUFFICIENT.
STRIKE THAT FROM
THE RECORD, MR. SPOCK.
YOU SEE, GENTLEMEN,
JUST AS I TOLD YOU.
3 LOVELY LADIES
DESTINED
FOR FRONTIER PLANETS
TO BE THE COMPANIONS
OF LONELY MEN,
TO SUPPLY THAT WARMTH
OF A HUMAN TOUCH THAT'S
SO DESPERATELY NEEDED--
A WIFE,
A HOME, A FAMILY.
GENTLEMEN,
I LOOK UPON THIS WORK
AS A SACRED PUBLIC TRUST.
I'VE DEVOTED
ME WHOLE LIFE TO IT.
INCORRECT.
WELL, I'M ABOUT TO START
DEVOTING MY ENTIRE LIFE TO IT.
DID THESE LADIES
COME VOLUNTARILY?
WELL, OF COURSE!
NOW, FOR EXAMPLE,
RUTHIE HERE COMES FROM
A PELAGIC PLANET--
SEA RANCHERS,
MAGDA THERE FROM THE HALIUM
EXPERIMENTAL STATION.
IT'S THE SAME STORY
FOR ALL OF US,
CAPTAIN--NO MEN.
MINE WAS A FARM PLANET
WITH AUTOMATED MACHINES
FOR COMPANY
AND 2 BROTHERS
TO COOK FOR,
MEND THEIR CLOTHES,
CANAL MUD A FOOT THICK
ON THEIR BOOTS EVERY TIME
THEY WALKED IN.
FINE, EVIE. FINE.
NO, IT'S NOT FINE!
WE'VE GOT MEN WILLING
TO BE OUR HUSBANDS
WAITING FOR US,
AND YOU'RE TAKING US
IN THE OPPOSITE DIRECTION!
STARING AT US
LIKE WE WERE SATURNIUS
HAREM GIRLS OR SOMETHING.
THAT'S ENOUGH, EVIE.
THE ONLY CHARGES
ARE AGAINST MR. MUDD.
ILLEGAL OPERATION
OF A VESSEL.
DO YOU HAVE ANY DEFENSE
TO OFFER?
ONLY HEAVEN'S OWN TRUTH,
WHICH I'VE JUST GIVEN YOU.
THE HEARING IS CLOSED...
MR. MUDD TO BE HANDED OVER
TO THE LEGAL AUTHORITIES
AT OUR EARLIEST OPPORTUNITY.
AND WHAT ABOUT US?
WHAT HAPPENS TO US?
HELP US, PLEASE.
ALL OF US.
MISS McHURON,
IF YOU DON'T MIND--
OUR LAST CRYSTAL, SIR.
IT'S GONE.
Sulu: CAPTAIN KIRK,
ENGINEERING SECTION REPORTS
OUR ENTIRE
LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEM
IS NOW ON BATTERIES.
MR. SPOCK--
MISS McHURON, PLEASE.
WOULD YOU MIND?
MR. SPOCK,
WILL YOU CONTACT
THE MINERS ON RIGEL-12?
NOTIFY THEM THAT WE'LL NEED
THE LITHIUM CRYSTALS
IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL.
OH, YOU BEAUTIFUL GALAXY!
OH, THAT HEAVENLY
UNIVERSE!
WELL, GIRLS,
LITHIUM MINERS.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
LONELY, ISOLATED,
OVERWORKED, RICH
LITHIUM MINERS!
GIRLS, DO YOU STILL
WANT HUSBANDS, HMM?
EVIE, YOU WON'T HAVE
TO BE SATISFIED WITH
A MERE SHIP'S CAPTAIN.
I'LL GET YOU A MAN
WHO CAN BUY YOU
A WHOLE PLANET.
MAGGIE, YOU'RE GOING
TO BE A COUNTESS.
RUTH, I'LL MAKE YOU
A DUCHESS.
AND I--
I'LL BE RUNNING
THIS STARSHIP.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK,
THE NEXT ORDERS YOU'RE TAKING
WILL BE GIVEN
BY HARCOURT FENTON MUDD!
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 1330.1.
POSITION--
14 HOURS OUT OF RIGEL-12.
WE'RE ON AUXILIARY
IMPULSE ENGINES.
FUEL LOW,
BARELY SUFFICIENT TO ACHIEVE
ORBIT OVER THE PLANET.
LITHIUM REPLACEMENTS
ARE NOW IMPERATIVE.
THE EFFECT OF MUDD'S WOMEN
ON MY CREW CONTINUES TO GROW,
STILL TOTALLY UNEXPLAINED.
HARRY MUDD IS CONFINED
TO HIS QUARTERS UNDER GUARD.
Ruth: MAY I COME IN?
WHY, YES. PLEASE DO.
BY ALL MEANS.
CONNORS,
ARE YOU FINISHED?
I WAS WONDERING
WHAT THIS PLACE
LOOKED LIKE.
[BEEPING]
IT'S FASCINATING.
WOULD--WOULD YOU
WALK PAST MY PANEL
AGAIN, PLEASE?
YOUR WHAT?
MY MEDICAL SCANNER.
OH, WHY?
YOU'RE NOT GIVING ME
AN EXAMINATION, ARE YOU?
NO. I WOULDN'T
TRUST MY--
MY JUDGMENT,
BELIEVE ME.
JUST WALK BY,
PLEASE.
[BEEPING]
IT'S NOT SUPPOSED
TO DO THAT.
I WONDERED,
WILL YOU BE EXAMINING
THE MINERS ON RIGEL-12?
YES, IF THEY NEED IT.
DO YOU MEAN YOU
HAVEN'T ASKED YET?
[BEEPING STOPS]
ARE THEY
IN GOOD HEALTH
AND ALL THAT?
WHAT?
OH, YES, THEY'RE
IN EXCELLENT HEALTH,
ALL 3 OF THEM.
OH. 3.
ARE YOU WEARING
SOME UNUSUAL
KIND OF PERFUME
OR SOMETHING
RADIOACTIVE,
MY DEAR?
NO. I'M JUST ME.
I WONDER WHAT
MAKES IT DO THAT.
Eve: CAPTAIN?
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
MISS McHURON, I DO.
I WAS TRYING
TO TAKE A WALK,
AND I JUST HAD TO
RUN IN SOMEPLACE.
YOU SEE, I MEAN,
ALL YOUR MEN
WERE LOOKING AT ME,
FOLLOWING ME
WITH THEIR EYES.
YES. I'LL HAVE TO
TALK TO THEM ABOUT THAT.
THEY, UH, THEY DON'T
DO THAT ORDINARILY,
MISS McHURON,
BUT SOMEHOW,
IN YOUR CASE,
AND THE LADIES
WITH YOU, IT'S...
WELL,
THEY'RE PROBABLY
JUST LONELY.
I CAN UNDERSTAND
LONELINESS.
YES.
YES, UH,
NOW, MISS McHURON,
IF YOU DON'T MIND--
I--I SUPPOSE--
I SUPPOSE
YOU UNDERSTAND IT
EVEN MORE.
I MEAN, HAVING TO RUN
A HUGE SHIP LIKE THIS
WITH SO MUCH
RESPONSIBILITY
EVERY MINUTE,
AND HAVING TO BE
SO CAREFUL
WITH ALL YOUR MEN
LOOKING UP TO YOU.
WELL, IT PROBABLY APPEARS
MORE DIFFICULT THAN IT IS.
HMM! I READ ONCE
A COMMANDER
HAS TO ACT LIKE
A PARAGON OF VIRTUE.
I NEVER MET A PARAGON.
NEITHER HAVE I.
WELL, OF COURSE NOT.
NO ONE IS.
BUT SOME PEOPLE
TRY TO PRETEND.
UM...
DO YOU, CAPTAIN?
MISS McHURON,
I DON'T--
OH, NO! OH!
I JUST CAN'T DO IT.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT HARRY MUDD SAYS.
I DO LIKE YOU,
BUT I JUST CAN'T
GO THROUGH WITH IT.
I HATE
THIS WHOLE THING!
Mudd: JUST 3?
YOU'RE SURE?
YES. THE MINERS
ARE HEALTHY
AND FAIRLY YOUNG.
LATER, DEAR. LATER.
MAGDA, DID YOU GET TO
YOUR COMMUNICATIONS MAN?
THE HEAD MINER
IS NAMED BEN CHILDRESS.
THE OTHERS ARE
GOSSETT AND BENTON.
AND THEY'VE
BEEN THERE--
ALMOST 3 YEARS NOW,
ALONE!
PERFECT. PERFECT.
3 OF THEM,
AND 3 LOVELY LADIES
HAS HARRY MUDD.
AND LITHIUM CRYSTALS,
MY DEAR,
ARE WORTH 300 TIMES
THEIR WEIGHT IN DIAMONDS,
THOUSANDS OF TIMES
THEIR WEIGHT IN GOLD.
BUT THEY'LL BE
DOWN THERE,
AND WE'LL BE UP HERE,
CIRCLING 100 MILES
ABOVE THEM.
AND THERE'S A GUARD
OUTSIDE YOUR DOOR,
HARRY.
YOU CAN'T GET OUT
OF YOUR CABIN.
NO, MY DEARS.
AFTER ONE MORE
LITTLE JOB FOR YOU,
IT WON'T BE HARRY MUDD
THAT'S TRAPPED.
IT WILL BE
A GENTLEMAN NAMED
JAMES T...
I DON'T LIKE YOU!
AND I'M NOT VERY HAPPY
WITH MYSELF, EITHER.
Mudd: WELL, I'M NOT
REALLY SURPRISED.
I'VE SEEN YOU
NOTICING
THE CAPTAIN.
WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO NOTICE THEM!
OH.
OH, HARRY.
I DON'T FEEL
VERY GOOD.
I THINK IT MUST BE
NEAR THE TIME.
I ASKED FOR
A PREORBITAL COURSE,
MR. FARRELL.
[BEEPS]
PREORBITAL COURSE
LOCKED IN, SIR.
THAT'S THE LAST TIME
I'M GIVING AN ORDER
TWICE, GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE DOWN
TO BATTERY POWER,
AND WE'RE LOW
ON THAT.
IT WILL GET US
TO RIGEL-12, SIR,
BUT IT'LL BE
A SHAKY ORBIT.
JUST HANG US IN THERE
LONG ENOUGH TO GET
6 CRYSTALS, SCOTTY.
THAT'S ALL WE NEED.
I'LL
GET YOU THERE.
RIDICULOUS.
WHAT ARE WE
RUNNING HERE?
DID YOU
EXAMINE THEM?
DID YOU EXAMINE EVE?
SHE REFUSED.
WELL, COME ON,
YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
WHAT IS IT?
IS IT THAT
WE'RE TIRED,
AND THEY'RE
BEAUTIFUL?
AND THEY ARE
INCREDIBLY
BEAUTIFUL.
ARE THEY, JIM?
ARE THEY ACTUALLY
MORE LOVELY,
POUND FOR POUND,
MEASUREMENT
FOR MEASUREMENT,
THAN ANY OTHER WOMEN
YOU'VE KNOWN?
OR IS IT THAT
THEY JUST...
WELL, ACT BEAUTIFUL.
NO, STRIKE THAT.
STRIKE THAT.
WHAT ARE THEY,
BONES?
YOU MEAN, ARE THEY
ALIEN ILLUSIONS?
THAT SORT OF THING?
I ASKED YOU FIRST.
NO...
AN ALIEN SMART ENOUGH
TO PULL THIS
WOULD BE SMART ENOUGH
TO KEEP MY MEDICAL SCANNER
FROM GOING "BLEEP!"
I DON'T FOLLOW YOU.
I DON'T EITHER.
SUB-SPACE
FREQUENCY OF 3-9.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
RIGEL-12. RIGEL-12.
Man:
THIS IS RIGEL-12.
COME IN,
ENTERPRISE.
WELL, THIS ISN'T EXACTLY
THE ENTERPRISE.
MY NAME IS HARRY MUDD.
TO WHOM HAVE I
THE PLEASURE
OF SPEAKING, SIR?
POWER CURVE
STILL DROPPING, CAPTAIN.
WE'LL
MAKE ORBIT, SIR.
A TEMPORARY ONE.
LAY IN. COMPUTER?
WE CAN
SUSTAIN THIS ORBIT
FOR 3 DAYS, 7 HOURS.
MORE THAN ENOUGH TIME.
COMMUNICATIONS,
HAVE A REPRESENTATIVE
OF THE RIGEL-12 MINERS
MEET US HERE
TO DISCUSS OUR NEED.
BEAM HIM UP FIRST PASS
OVER THEIR CAMP.
YES, SIR.
LOOK WHAT'S
HAPPENING!
LOOK AT MY FACE.
GIVE US THE PILLS.
WHAT IF SOMEONE
SEES US LIKE THIS?
YOU'LL NEVER
FIND THEM, HARRY.
AND IF YOU DO FIND THEM,
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY ARE?
A CHEAT.
IF YOU...CARE FOR SOMEONE,
REALLY CARE--
FOR WHOM, EVIE?
FOR KIRK?
YOU'LL FIND OUT THAT
SHIP'S CAPTAINS ARE
ALREADY MARRIED, GIRL,
TO THEIR VESSELS.
YOU'D FIND THAT OUT
THE FIRST TIME
YOU CAME BETWEEN
HIM AND THE SHIP.
YOU'LL SEE.
I'M GOING BACK
TO WHAT I WAS--UGLY.
I CAN'T STAND MYSELF
LIKE THIS.
WHY DID YOU
HIDE THEM, HARRY?
DON'T YOU TRUST US?
I DIDN'T HIDE THEM,
GIRL.
I PUT THEM IN A SAFE PLACE
IN CASE I WAS SEARCHED.
FIND THE PILL,
HARRY!
MATTRESS!
YES! HERE!
GO ON, EVE.
TAKE IT.
IT'S NOT A CHEAT.
IT'S A MIRACLE...
FOR SOME MAN
WHO CAN APPRECIATE IT
AND WHO NEEDS IT.
Spock: EVEN
BURNED AND CRACKED,
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
DESTROYING THEM
WAS A SHAME.
NOT AT ALL, MR. SPOCK.
THE CHOICE WAS BURNING
THIS LITHIUM CRYSTAL
OR THE DESTRUCTION
OF ANOTHER MAN'S SHIP.
[BUZZER]
COME.
SIR, MINING CHIEF
CHILDRESS
AND MR. GOSSETT.
GOOD. SHOW THEM IN.
I'M JAMES KIRK,
CAPTAIN OF THE ENTERPRISE.
THIS IS
MY SCIENCE OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
LET'S GET
RIGHT TO BUSINESS.
YOU WANT
LITHIUM CRYSTALS,
AND WE'VE GOT THEM.
FINE.
I'M AUTHORIZED TO PAY
AN EQUITABLE PRICE.
WE'RE NOT SURE
THEY'RE FOR SALE,
CAPTAIN.
WE MIGHT PREFER
A SWAP.
WHAT DID YOU HAVE
IN MIND?
MUDD'S WOMEN.
IF WE LIKE THEM.
WE'D LIKE TO HAVE
A LOOK AT THEM FIRST,
OF COURSE.
RIGHT. TROT THEM
OUT, CAPTAIN.
OH, AND HARRY MUDD--
EITHER WAY,
I'VE AGREED TO
HAVE HIM RELEASED.
CHARGES DROPPED.
HA HA HA!
IS THERE
ANYTHING ELSE?
YOU'VE GOT
NO CHOICE, KIRK.
YOU BEAM A LANDING
PARTY DOWN,
AND YOU WON'T FIND
ONE BLESSED CRYSTAL.
NO DEAL.
YOU'RE A LONG WAY
OUT IN SPACE, GENTLEMEN.
YOU'LL NEED
MEDICAL HELP,
CARGO RUNS,
STARSHIP PROTECTION.
YOU WANT TO CONSIDER
THOSE FACTS, TOO?
COME ALONG, LADIES.
COME ALONG.
YOU MUST BE
BEN CHILDRESS.
COME ON NOW, GIRLS.
COME ON.
AND YOU MUST BE
HERM GOSSETT.
Gossett:
YES, I RECKON I AM.
ONE THING I'LL SAY
FOR YOU, MUDD--
YOU'RE NOT A LIAR.
LADIES,
YOU ARE WELCOME.
Kirk:
IT'S STILL NO DEAL!
CONSERVING BATTERIES,
SIR. HALF POWER.
I'M TOLD THEY HAVE
ONLY 3 DAYS OF ORBIT LEFT
BEFORE THEY START
SPIRALING IN.
TSK TSK TSK.
I DO HATE
TO SEE YOU SUFFERING
SUCH A SITUATION, CAPTAIN,
BUT TRUTH IS TRUTH,
AND THE SAD FACT IS,
YOU WILL DEAL.
SOONER OR LATER,
YOU'LL HAVE TO.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
TRANSPORTING DOWN TO SURFACE
OF PLANET RIGEL-12
TO ACQUIRE REPLACEMENT
LITHIUM CRYSTALS.
EXPECT FURTHER DIFFICULTY
FROM MINERS.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
ALL RIGHT, CHILDRESS.
YOU'VE WON.
NOW I'LL TAKE
THE LITHIUM CRYSTALS.
WHEN I HAVE
THE TIME, KIRK.
HA HA HA!
CHILDRESS.
WE'RE BUSY,
MR. KIRK.
WE...DON'T HAVE
THE TIME TO SPARE,
CAPTAIN.
YOU GOT A BETTER IDEA?
BLOWS LIKE THAT
ALL THE TIME.
[WIND HOWLING]
YOU CAN GET LOST
A DOZEN FEET
FROM YOUR OWN DOORSTEP,
THE WIND COMES UP SUDDEN.
[CRACKLING]
MAGNETIC STORM.
THAT MEANS THE WIND
WILL REALLY RIP SOON.
DANCE WITH ME.
WOULD YOU
LIKE TO DANCE?
NO, I--
[COUGHING]
NO.
I'M SORRY.
I GUESS IT MUST BE
THE DUST.
THAT'S THE WAY
IT IS ON RIGEL...
ALL THE TIME.
[LAUGHING]
HEY.
GO AWAY.
I'M CUTTING IN.
NOT ON ME.
Mudd: WHAT'S
THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WHY DON'T YOU JUST
RUN A RAFFLE
AND THE LOSER GETS ME?
Miner: YOU CAN'T
GO OUT THERE!
YOU'LL GET KILLED.
JUST HAVE
THOSE CRYSTALS HERE
WHEN I GET BACK.
EVE!
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
HAVE TRANSPORTED ABOARD
THE ENTERPRISE
TO IMPLEMENT SEARCH
WITH INFRARED SCANNERS
AND SENSING SYSTEM.
MAGNETIC STORMS
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE
ARE CUTTING DOWN
SPEED AND EFFICIENCY
OF OUR EQUIPMENT.
SEARCH NOW IN PROGRESS
FOR 3 HOURS, 18 MINUTES.
TRAVERSE PARALLEL
3 AND 4.
CHECKING...
BUT NOT
GETTING MUCH.
THE STORM IS IONIZING
THE ATMOSPHERE, CAPTAIN.
GETTING DIFFICULT
TO PROBE THROUGH IT.
CAPTAIN,
THIS IS DRAINING OUR
BATTERIES FURTHER.
IF WE ONLY HAD
THOSE CRYSTALS.
BUT WE DON'T!
I DIDN'T GET ANY.
I SHOULD HAVE FOUND A WAY.
SATISFIED, MR. SCOTT?
LOSING COMMUNICATIONS
WITH THE MINERS, SIR.
MAGNETIC STORM
SEEMS WORSE.
HAS CHILDRESS
REPORTED IN YET?
NO, SIR. HE AND THE GIRL
ARE STILL MISSING.
SORRY, SCOTTY.
HOW MUCH POWER
DO WE HAVE LEFT?
ABOUT
5 HOURS, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
HAVE EXPENDED ALL BUT
43 MINUTES OF POWER.
SHIP'S CONDITION--
CRITICAL.
SEARCH NOW IN PROGRESS
7 HOURS, 31 MINUTES.
MAGNETIC STORMS
ARE EASING.
INFRARED READING.
CHECK TRAVERSE 3,
GRID 0-4-0.
ABOUT 11 MILES.
BEARING 1-2-1 FROM
THE MINING COMPANY.
Sulu: THAT'S
BEN CHILDRESS'
QUARTERS.
THERE'S A HEAT UNIT
OPERATING THERE.
IT COULD BE
A COOKSTOVE.
HAVE MUDD MEET ME
IN THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM.
MUDD?
THE NAME
OF THIS GAME.
[THUDS]
I HAD THINGS
WHERE I WANTED THEM.
I ATE
SOME OF YOUR FOOD,
SO I PAID
WITH SOME CHORES.
AND I DO
MY OWN COOKING.
AAH!
I'VE NOT LAID
A HAND ON YOU.
REMEMBER THAT.
OH, THE SOUND
OF MALE EGO.
YOU TRAVEL HALFWAY
ACROSS THE GALAXY,
AND IT'S STILL
THE SAME SONG.
THERE. YOU GOING
TO EAT OR TALK?
I GUESS I'M SUPPOSED TO SIT,
TASTE, AND ROLL MY EYES.
"OOH,
FEMALE COOKING AGAIN."
I'VE TASTED BETTER...
BY MY OWN HAND.
YOU'RE TASTING
SOME OF IT NOW.
I COULDN'T SCRAPE
3 LAYERS
OF YOUR LEAVINGS
OUT OF THAT PAN.
YOU FIND ME A WELL,
SOME DECENT WATER.
THEN TALK.
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU
HANG YOUR PAN
OUT IN THE WIND
AND LET THE SAND
BLAST IT CLEAN?
OR HADN'T YOU
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT?
IT MIGHT WORK.
THAT SOLITAIRE?
DOUBLE JACK.
THE RED 8
OUGHT TO GO
ON THE BLACK 9.
NOT IN DOUBLE JACK.
YOU'RE NOT ONLY PLAIN
AS AN OLD BUCKET,
YOU'RE NOT EVEN
GOOD COMPANY.
WHAT THE DEVIL HAPPENED
TO YOUR LOOKS, ANYWAY?
I GOT TIRED OF YOU.
I SLUMPED.
YOU HEARD
WHAT I SAID.
YOU'RE HOMELY!
I'VE GOT ENOUGH
IN CRYSTALS ALREADY
TO BUY QUEENS...
BY THE GROSS!
I DIDN'T TOUCH HER.
THANK HEAVEN
YOU FOUND HER.
SHE'S BEEN BUBBLING
WITH GRATITUDE
EVER SINCE.
SIT DOWN.
TELL HIM.
TELL HIM, HARRY.
AH. YES, WELL--
THE VENUS DRUGS, HARRY.
VENUS DRUG?
I'VE HEARD
OF IT, BUT...
ISN'T THAT
JUST ONE OF
THOSE STORIES?
OH, IT EXISTS...
ILLEGALLY.
WELL,
ACTUALLY, YOU SEE,
IT'S A RELATIVELY
HARMLESS DRUG.
HARMLESS?
YEAH, UH...
WELL,
WHAT IT DOES IS
GIVE YOU MORE
OF WHATEVER YOU HAVE.
WELL, WITH MEN,
IT MAKES THEM
MORE MUSCULAR.
WOMEN, ROUNDER.
MEN, MORE AGGRESSIVE.
WOMEN, MORE FEMININE, AND--
HE GAVE IT TO THE WOMEN
BEFORE YOU MET THEM.
DOES THAT MEAN
THE OTHERS...
THEY REALLY LOOK
LIKE SHE DOES?
MR. CHILDRESS, I--
IS THAT
WHAT IT MEANS?
YES, THAT'S
WHAT IT MEANS!
WHAT HAPPENED
TO MY PARTNERS?
THEY'VE LEFT FOR
THEIR QUARTERS DURING
THE STORM, CHILDRESS.
THEY'RE MARRIED--
SUBSPACE RADIO MARRIAGE.
IT WAS A FRAUD.
THEY CAN GET OUT OF IT.
IF THEY WANT TO.
WHY?
Mudd: YOU CAN'T
CONDEMN THE WOMEN.
I CAN!
A MAN GOES OUT
AND FIGHTS,
ALMOST DIES.
WE ALL ALMOST DIE.
WE SHOULD HAVE,
BUT WE DIDN'T.
AND NOW THAT WE'VE
GOT THE GOOD LIFE
IN OUR HANDS,
YOU BRING US WOMEN
FOR WIVES THAT--
YOU DON'T WANT WIVES!
YOU WANT THIS.
THIS IS WHAT YOU WANT,
MR. CHILDRESS.
AND I HOPE
YOU REMEMBER IT
AND DREAM ABOUT IT,
BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T HAVE IT!
IT'S NOT REAL!
IS THIS THE KIND
OF WIFE YOU WANT, BEN?
NOT SOMEONE
TO HELP YOU.
NOT A WIFE TO COOK
AND SEW AND CRY
AND NEED,
BUT THIS KIND?
SELFISH,
VAIN,
USELESS.
IS THIS WHAT
YOU REALLY WANT?
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
HERE IT IS.
QUITE A WOMAN,
EH, CHILDRESS?
A FAKE...
PUMPED UP BY A DRUG.
BY HERSELF.
SHE TOOK NO DRUG.
I SWALLOWED IT.
COLORED GELATIN.
YES, THEY TOOK AWAY
MY DRUG
AND SUBSTITUTED THAT.
BUT THAT CAN'T BE.
THERE'S ONLY ONE
KIND OF WOMAN.
OR MAN,
FOR THAT MATTER.
YOU EITHER BELIEVE
IN YOURSELF,
OR YOU DON'T.
ALL RIGHT,
CHILDRESS.
I'VE GONE
AS FAR WITH YOU
AS I INTEND TO.
I WANT THOSE
LITHIUM CRYSTALS,
AND I WANT THEM NOW.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS KIRK.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
STAND BY.
DO I BEAM DOWN
A SEARCH PARTY?
NO.
THE CRYSTALS
ARE HERE,
AND YOU'RE WELCOME
TO THEM.
STAND BY, MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE COMING ABOARD
WITH THE LITHIUM
CRYSTALS.
Spock:
HOW MANY COMING,
CAPTAIN?
EVE WILL STAY...
TODAY, AT LEAST.
WE, UH...
WE WANT TO TALK.
EVE?
YOU'VE GOT SOMEONE
UP THERE CALLED
THE ENTERPRISE.
2 OF US,
MR. SPOCK.
COME ALONG,
MR. MUDD.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU COULD POSSIBLY,
BY ACCIDENT,
ARRANGE TO
LEAVE ME BEHIND HERE?
ON THIS PLANET,
THAT WOULD BE
PUNISHMENT ENOUGH.
I CAN'T DO THAT,
HARRY.
BUT I WILL APPEAR AS
A CHARACTER WITNESS
AT YOUR TRIAL,
IF YOU THINK
THAT'LL HELP.
THEY'LL THROW AWAY
THE KEY.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
QUITE A TALK YOU
MADE DOWN THERE.
EVER TRY CONSIDERING
THE PATENT MEDICINE
BUSINESS?
WHY SHOULD I WORK
YOUR SIDE OF THE STREET?
I'M HAPPY
THE AFFAIR IS OVER.
A MOST ANNOYING
EMOTIONAL EPISODE.
SMACK RIGHT IN
THE OLD HEART.
OH, I'M SORRY.
IN YOUR CASE,
IT WOULD BE
ABOUT HERE.
THE FACT THAT
MY INTERNAL ARRANGEMENT
DIFFERS FROM YOURS, DOCTOR,
PLEASES ME NO END.
Farrell:
COURSE PLOTTED
AND ALL SYSTEMS
IN OPERATION.
Sulu:
ENGINES ENGAGED.
HELM ANSWERING.
OUT OF ORBIT, SIR.
AHEAD FULL.
AHEAD FULL, SIR.