ALL SECTIONS--
SECURITY CHECK IN PROGRESS.
REPORT.
WE'RE ENTERING
STANDARD ORBIT, NURSE.
IT WON'T BE MUCH LONGER.
FORWARD SCANNER
TO BRIDGE.
I UNDERSTAND YOU GAVE UP
A CAREER IN BIO-RESEARCH
TO SIGN ABOARD A STARSHIP.
I KNOW HE'S ALIVE
DOWN THERE, CAPTAIN.
SCANNER TO BRIDGE,
STATUS REPORT, PLEASE.
IT'S BEEN FIVE YEARS
SINCE HIS LAST MESSAGE.
ROGER'S
A VERY DETERMINED MAN.
HE'D FIND A WAY TO LIVE.
BEGINNING SIGNALS
TO SURFACE, SIR.
PUT IT ON ALL
FREQUENCIES, LIEUTENANT.
SHIP'S RECORD BANKS
SHOW LITTLE WE DON'T
ALREADY KNOW
ABOUT THIS PLANET,
CAPTAIN.
GRAVITY IS 1.1 OF EARTH.
ATMOSPHERE WITHIN
SAFETY LIMITS.
BUT THE SURFACE
TEMPERATURE
OF THAT PLANET
IS 100 DEGREES BELOW 0.
IT MAY HAVE BEEN
INHABITED ONCE,
BUT THE SUN
IN THIS SYSTEM
HAS BEEN FADING STEADILY
FOR A HALF MILLION YEARS.
NOW DR. KORBY--
OFTEN CALLED THE PASTEUR
OF ARCHAEOLOGICAL MEDICINE.
HIS TRANSLATION
OF MEDICAL RECORDS
FROM THE ORION RUINS
REVOLUTIONIZED
OUR IMMUNIZATION
TECHNIQUES.
REQUIRED READING AT
THE ACADEMY, MR. SPOCK.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO MEET HIM.
DO YOU THINK
THERE'S ANY CHANCE OF
HIM STILL BEING ALIVE?
I'VE TRIED
ALL FREQUENCIES, SIR.
NO RETURN SIGNAL.
KEEP TRYING.
WARP CAPACITY
.07 AND BUILDING.
COMMUNICATOR,
WE NEED MORE LINES
TO THE IMPULSE DECK.
HIS LAST SIGNAL
TOLD ABOUT FINDING
UNDERGROUND CAVERNS.
AND SINCE THEN
TWO EXPEDITIONS HAVE
FAILED TO FIND HIM.
I'VE RUN ALL FREQUENCIES
A SECOND TIME, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NO--
[BEEP BEEP]
ENTERPRISE,
COME IN, ENTERPRISE.
THIS IS ROGER KORBY.
REPEATING--
THIS IS DR. ROGER KORBY.
DO YOU READ ME,
ENTERPRISE?
THIS IS
DR. ROGER KORBY...
STANDING BY.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 2712.4.
A SIGNAL
FROM PLANET EXO-III.
DR. ROGER KORBY
HAS BEEN LOCATED,
HE AND PART OF HIS
EXPEDITION REMAINING ALIVE
DUE TO THE DISCOVERY
OF UNDERGROUND RUINS
LEFT BY THE FORMER
INHABITANTS OF THIS WORLD.
ENTERPRISE TO KORBY,
WE HAVE YOUR LANDING
COORDINATES PINPOINTED.
WE'RE PREPARING
TO BEAM DOWN A PARTY.
IT MAY INTEREST YOU
THAT WE HAVE ABOARD
THIS VESSEL--
I'VE AN UNUSUAL
REQUEST, CAPTAIN KIRK.
BEAM DOWN ALONE,
JUST YOURSELF.
WE'VE MADE DISCOVERIES
OF SUCH A NATURE
THEY MAY REQUIRE
AN EXTRAORDINARY
DECISION FROM YOU.
THAT IS AN UNUSUAL REQUEST.
THE MAN MAKING IT
IS DR. ROGER KORBY.
YOU'RE CERTAIN
YOU RECOGNIZE HIS VOICE?
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
ENGAGED, MR. SPOCK?
OH, YES,
IT'S ROGER.
AGREED, DOCTOR.
HOWEVER, THERE
WILL BE TWO OF US.
HELLO, ROGER.
CHRISTINE?
YES, ROGER.
DARLING, HOW--
WHERE ARE YOU?
YES, YES, BY ALL MEANS,
CAPTAIN.
I--I HAD
NO IDEA, NO HOPE.
DARLING,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, ROGER.
EVERYTHING'S
ALL RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY,
DOCTOR.
WE'LL BE WITH YOU
IN A MOMENT.
ENTERPRISE OUT.
ENERGIZE.
HE SAID HE'D BE WAITING.
DR. KORBY.
IT'S POSSIBLE WE MAY HAVE
HIT THE WRONG ENTRY POINT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
BEAM DOWN...
TWO SECURITY MEN.
ANY PROBLEMS,
CAPTAIN?
SOME DELAY
IN MEETING US.
PROBABLY NOTHING
AT ALL. KIRK OUT.
CORRIDORS COULD BE
QUITE DEEP.
GETTING HERE MAY
HAVE TAKEN MORE TIME
THAN HE ESTIMATED.
DON'T WORRY.
THANK YOU.
RAYBURN,
MAINTAIN POST HERE.
YES, SIR.
MATHEWS, WE'LL LOOK FOR
DR. KORBY. YOU ACCOMPANY US.
YES, SIR.
AAH!
[CLATTERING]
IS THAT YOU,
DR. KORBY?
DR. BROWN!
IT'S ROGER'S ASSISTANT.
BROWNIE, WHERE'S ROGER?
[MAN SCREAMING]
BE CAREFUL!
PLEASE, BE CAREFUL.
IS THERE
A PATH DOWN THERE?
THERE'S NO HOPE,
CAPTAIN. IT'S BOTTOMLESS.
HE MUST HAVE SLIPPED.
ANY CHANCE OF
A PROJECTION OR A LEDGE?
NONE, CAPTAIN.
UNFORTUNATE.
TERRIBLY UNFORTUNATE.
DR. KORBY WAS DETAINED.
I CAME
AS SOON AS I COULD.
NOT SOON ENOUGH.
BROWNIE,
WHAT IS IT?
EXPLAIN.
DON'T YOU RECOGNIZE ME?
CHRISTINE.
YOU LOOK WELL.
MY NAME IS BROWN,
DR. KORBY'S ASSISTANT.
I PRESUME
YOU ARE CAPTAIN KIRK.
HE'S DEAD.
I ASSURE YOU.
COME.
DR. KORBY
WILL BE WAITING.
YOU DO KNOW HIM WELL?
AN OLD FRIEND?
WELL, I SUPPOSE LIVING HERE
FOR FIVE YEARS...
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO RAYBURN. REPORT.
ALL QUIET HERE
AT THE ENTRY, CAPTAIN.
ANY PROBLEMS THERE, SIR?
WE LOST MATHEWS.
APPARENTLY AN ACCIDENT.
TELL THE ENTERPRISE
TO HAVE A FULL SECURITY
PARTY STANDING BY.
YES, SIR.
AND WE'LL BOTH REPORT
IN AT HOURLY INTERVALS.
IF YOU AND I
LOSE CONTACT,
OR IF HE FAILS TO HEAR
FROM EITHER OF US,
HE'S TO BEAM
THE SECURITY PARTY DOWN
IMMEDIATELY. KIRK OUT.
DR. KORBY HAS DISCOVERED
THAT AS THEIR SUN DIMMED,
THE INHABITANTS
OF THIS PLANET
MOVED UNDERGROUND
FROM AN OPEN ENVIRONMENT
TO THIS DARK WORLD.
WHEN YOU WERE
A STUDENT OF HIS,
CHRISTINE,
YOU MUST HAVE OFTEN
HEARD DR. KORBY REMARK
HOW FREEDOM OF MOVEMENT
AND CHOICE PRODUCED
THE HUMAN SPIRIT.
THE CULTURE OF EXO-III
PROVED HIS THEORY.
WHEN THEY MOVED
FROM LIGHT TO DARKNESS,
THEY REPLACED FREEDOM
WITH A MECHANISTIC CULTURE.
DR. KORBY HAS BEEN ABLE
TO UNCOVER ELEMENTS
OF THIS CULTURE
WHICH WILL REVOLUTIONIZE
THE UNIVERSE
WHEN FREED FROM
THIS CAVERNOUS ENVIRONMENT.
I'M ANDREA.
YOU MUST BE CHRISTINE.
I'VE ALWAYS THOUGHT HOW
BEAUTIFUL YOUR NAME IS.
AND YOU
MUST BE CAPTAIN KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
WE APPRECIATE
YOU BRINGING ROGER'S
FIANCÉE TO HIM.
I DON'T REMEMBER DR. KORBY
MENTIONING AN ANDREA.
BUT YOU ARE EXACTLY
AS ROGER DESCRIBED YOU.
NO WONDER
HE MISSED YOU SO.
WHERE IS DR. KORBY?
HERE, CAPTAIN.
I, UH...
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
FORWARD TO--
OH, I KNEW
I'D FIND YOU.
EVERYTHING'S
ALL RIGHT NOW.
OH.
FORGIVE ME, CAPTAIN.
I'M, UH, I'M ROGER KORBY.
THERE'S NO NEED
TO APOLOGIZE, SIR,
AND CERTAINLY NO NEED
TO INTRODUCE YOURSELF.
THE CAPTAIN LOST
A MAN IN THE CAVERNS,
DOCTOR.
WHAT?
HOW DID IT HAPPEN?
THE PIT NEAR
THE OUTER JUNCTION.
THE EDGE
MUST HAVE GIVEN WAY.
I'M TERRIBLY SORRY,
CAPTAIN.
PERHAPS
IF I'D BEEN THERE--
I KNOW THE PASSAGES
SO WELL.
IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
KIRK TO RAYBURN. REPORT.
I'M REQUIRED TO MAKE
A SECURITY CONFIRMATION.
WHEN I CALL MY SHIP,
IF YOU LIST YOUR PERSONNEL,
CARGO REQUIREMENTS,
ANY SPECIAL NEEDS--
CAPTAIN,
I'D MUCH PREFER--
RAYBURN,
ARE YOU RECEIVING?
I'D PREFER YOU WAITED,
CAPTAIN,
PLEASE, TILL
I'VE TALKED TO YOU.
I'VE LOST CONTACT
WITH MY GUARD.
I MUST CALL MY SHIP.
NO COMMUNICATIONS,
CAPTAIN.
ROGER!
I'M SORRY.
IF THEY SHOULD SEND
DOWN MORE PEOPLE--
ROGER, THAT--
HE WON'T BE HARMED.
I PROMISE YOU.
ISN'T IT POSSIBLE THERE
COULD BE THINGS HERE
UNKNOWN TO YOU
SO TERRIBLY IMPORTANT--
SIR, ONE MAN IS DEAD.
I'VE LOST CONTACT
WITH THE OTHER.
ANDREA.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THIS IS NECESSARY,
CAPTAIN.
YOU WILL UNDERSTAND.
ANDREA.
DROP IT!
[CHRISTINE]
OHH!
ENTERPRISE
FROM CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN. DO YOU READ?
FREQUENCY OPEN,
MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
CONTACT ESTABLISHED
WITH DR. KORBY.
WE WERE BECOMING
CONCERNED, CAPTAIN.
YOUR CHECK-IN WAS OVERDUE,
AND SINCE WE'D NOT HEARD
FROM YOUR SECURITY TEAM--
NO PROBLEM, MR. SPOCK.
BEAR WITH ME.
[KIRK'S VOICE]
WE'LL RETURN TO THE SHIP
WITHIN 48 HOURS.
DR. KORBY'S RECORDS
AND SPECIMENS WILL
REQUIRE CAREFUL PACKING.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YOU SOUND TIRED.
IF YOU MOVE OR CRY OUT,
RUK MAY INJURE YOU.
AT LEAST WAIT
UNTIL YOU AND I
CAN TALK.
[SPOCK]
ACKNOWLEDGE, CAPTAIN.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
FINE, MR. SPOCK.
DR. KORBY HAS MADE SOME
FASCINATING DISCOVERIES.
ALL UNDER CONTROL.
STAND BY FOR REGULAR
CONTACT. KIRK OUT.
THIS IS NOT
A VAIN DISPLAY, CAPTAIN.
I'M A SCIENTIST.
YOU OBVIOUSLY KNOW
OF MY REPUTATION.
TRUST ME.
YES, I KNOW
YOUR REPUTATION.
THE WHOLE GALAXY
KNOWS WHO YOU ARE
AND WHAT YOU STAND FOR.
THAT'S WHY ALL THIS
MAKES NO SENSE.
THERE IS SO MUCH
YOU MUST LEARN
BEFORE YOU MAKE
A FINAL JUDGMENT.
FOR EXAMPLE...
ANDREA.
[ANDREA'S VOICE]
YOU MUST BE
CAPTAIN KIRK...
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
[KORBY'S VOICE]
CHRISTINE,
IT'S ALL RIGHT NOW.
YOU SEE, CAPTAIN?
[CHRISTINE'S VOICE]
YES, ROGER.
EVERYTHING
IS ALL RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU ARE NOT
TO MOCK CHRISTINE.
YOU WILL
NEVER HARM HER.
OR DISOBEY
AN ORDER FROM HER.
YOU WILL NOT DISOBEY
HER ORDERS.
SATISFIED,
CAPTAIN KIRK?
BOTH LOVE AND TRUST.
NOW GIVE ME 24 HOURS
TO CONVINCE YOU.
DOCTOR, DO I NEED
TO BE A PRISONER
TO BE CONVINCED?
WHAT WOULD
YOUR FIRST DUTY BE UPON
RETURN TO YOUR VESSEL?
A REPORT. DO YOU
REALIZE THE NUMBER
OF DISCOVERIES LOST
BECAUSE OF SUPERSTITION?
OF IGNORANCE?
OF A LAYMAN'S INABILITY
TO COMPREHEND?
A SIMPLE LAYMAN'S
QUESTION, DOCTOR...
WHERE IS
MY OTHER CREWMAN?
ALIVE?
DEAD?
RUK WAS PROGRAMMED TO
PROTECT MY EXPERIMENTS.
THE LOGIC OF HIS MACHINE
MIND SAW DANGER TO ME.
WHERE IS MY OTHER CREWMAN?
RUK DESTROYED THEM BOTH,
BUT TOTALLY AGAINST
MY WISHES, I ASSURE YOU.
HE'S AN ANDROID...
LIKE BROWN?
MORE COMPLEX THAN BROWN.
MUCH SUPERIOR.
I WAS LEFT HERE
BY THE OLD ONES.
RUK WAS STILL
TENDING THE MACHINERY
WHEN WE ARRIVED HERE.
HOW MANY CENTURIES?
EVEN RUK DOESN'T KNOW.
WITH HIS HELP,
WITH THE RECORDS
I COULD FIND,
WE BUILT BROWN.
YOU'VE CONVINCED ME,
DOCTOR.
YOU'VE CONVINCED ME
THAT YOU'RE DANGEROUS.
[CRASH]
RUK, NO!
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHY ARE YOU UNHAPPY?
YOU ARE
WITH ROGER AGAIN.
WHERE IS CAPTAIN KIRK?
YOU ARE CONCERNED
ABOUT THE CAPTAIN?
YES, I AM CONCERNED.
HOW CAN YOU LOVE ROGER
WITHOUT TRUSTING HIM?
WHY DOES IT
BOTHER YOU WHEN
I USE THE NAME ROGER?
ANDREA,
IT'S SUFFICIENT THAT
IT DOES DISTURB HER.
YOU WILL CALL ME
DR. KORBY FROM
NOW ON, ANDREA.
YES, DR. KORBY.
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO EAVESDROP, DARLING.
AS YOU CAN SEE, UH,
CAPTAIN KIRK IS FINE.
HE WON'T BE HARMED.
THE THINGS AT STAKE HERE
SIMPLY MAKE IT NECESSARY
HE DOESN'T SEND
A REPORT TO HIS SHIP.
I NEED TIME TO EXPLAIN
AND DEMONSTRATE...
TO HIM AND TO YOU.
NOW SHALL
WE START WITH ANDREA?
YES, LET'S
START WITH ANDREA.
I'M LIKE DR. BROWN--
AN ANDROID.
DIDN'T YOU KNOW?
REMARKABLE, ISN'T SHE?
NOTICE THE--
THE LIFELIKE
PIGMENTATION,
THE VARIATION
IN SKIN TONES.
THE FLESH--
THE FLESH HAS WARMTH.
THERE'S EVEN A PULSE,
PHYSICAL SENSATION.
HOW CONVENIENT.
CHRISTINE,
YOU MUST REALIZE
AN ANDROID IS
LIKE A COMPUTER.
IT DOES ONLY
WHAT I PROGRAM.
AS A TRAINED
SCIENTIST YOURSELF,
YOU MUST REALIZE--
THAT GIVEN
A MECHANICAL DR. BROWN,
A MECHANICAL GEISHA
WOULD BE NO MORE DIFFICULT.
YOU THINK I COULD LOVE
A MACHINE?
DID YOU?
ANDREA'S INCAPABLE
OF THAT.
SHE SIMPLY OBEYS ORDERS.
SHE HAS
NO MEANING FOR ME.
THERE'S
NO EMOTIONAL BOND.
ANDREA...
KISS, UH, CAPTAIN KIRK.
NOW STRIKE HIM.
YOU SEE?
THERE'S NO EMOTION IN IT,
NO EMOTIONAL INVOLVEMENT.
SHE SIMPLY RESPONDS
TO ORDERS.
SHE'S A TOTALLY
LOGICAL COMPUTER,
A THING.
NOT A WOMAN.
NOW DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
IF THESE MECHANICAL
THINGS HAVE NO FEELINGS
AND PERFORM ONLY
AS YOU PROGRAM THEM,
THEN WHY DID BROWN
TRY TO SHOOT ME?
WHY DID HE KILL
TWO OF MY MEN?
THERE ARE
MANY THINGS I DON'T
UNDERSTAND, DOCTOR.
I WILL ANSWER ALL OF
YOUR QUESTIONS...NOW.
THIS IS HOW
YOU MAKE AN ANDROID.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
ANDREA.
[LOW RUMBLING]
HE'S NOT BEING HARMED.
I PROMISE.
ROGER,
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU?
WHEN I SAT
IN YOUR CLASS,
YOU WOULDN'T
EVEN DREAM OF HARMING
AN INSECT OR AN ANIMAL.
THEIR LIFE WAS
SACRED TO YOU THEN.
CHRISTINE,
IF I'D SIMPLY BEAMED UP
TO THEIR VESSEL
WITH BROWN
AND THE OTHERS,
I'D HAVE GIVEN THEM
OBJECTS OF CURIOSITY,
BEGINNINGS
OF WILD STORIES,
FOOLISH THEORIES.
RUK!
[HIGH-PITCHED SQUEALING]
NOW WATCH CAREFULLY.
CHOOSE, CHRISTINE.
WHICH IS YOUR CAPTAIN?
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY'RE EXACT.
I HONESTLY DON'T KNOW.
SYNTHETIC ORGANS
ARE IN PLACE.
WE MERELY
SYNCHRONIZE THEM
WITH KIRK'S
AUTONOMIC
NERVOUS SYSTEM,
DUPLICATING
THE RHYTHMS
OF HIS BODY.
AT THE SAME TIME,
WE DUPLICATE
THE MENTAL PATTERN.
NOW...
PHYSICAL PATTERN
COMPLETE,
WE NOW MAKE
A MENTAL PATTERN.
READY FOR FINAL
SYNAPTIC FUSION.
ANDREA, STAND BY
FOR CORTEX CIRCUITS.
THE ANDROID
WILL BE SO PERFECT,
IT COULD EVEN
REPLACE THE CAPTAIN.
THE SAME MEMORIES,
THE SAME ATTITUDES,
THE SAME ABILITIES.
ACTIVATE CIRCUITS.
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS,
MR. SPOCK.
I'M SICK OF YOUR
HALF-BREED INTERFERENCE,
DO YOU HEAR ME?
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS,
MR. SPOCK.
I'M SICK OF YOUR--
[BUZZ]
[STATIC]
COMPLETE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
NOW...
MEET AN ANDROID.
HOW DO YOU DO,
MISS CHAPEL?
I AM NOW PROGRAMMED
TO PLEASE YOU ALSO.
IS THE FOOD
APPEALING?
YES, THANK YOU.
PLEASE SIT,
CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
I'M MORE OR LESS
ON PAROLE, I UNDERSTAND.
DR. KORBY SUGGESTED
THAT YOU HAVE LUNCH.
HE THOUGHT YOU MIGHT HAVE
A FEW THINGS TO TALK ABOUT.
CAPTAIN...
I KNOW, I KNOW.
I'D HATE TO BE TORN
BETWEEN COMMANDER
AND FIANCÉE MYSELF.
NO, I'M NOT TORN.
I'M PUZZLED.
I'M WORRIED.
HAS HE CONFIDED IN YOU?
NO, NOTHING
HE HASN'T TOLD YOU.
I KNOW
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WHAT HE'S DONE
MAY SEEM WRONG,
BUT HE IS ROGER KORBY,
WHATEVER
HE SEEMS TO BE DOING.
UNLESS SOMETHING'S
GONE WRONG WITH HIS MIND.
NO. YOU'RE FORGETTING
HOW WELL I KNOW HIM.
HE'S AS SANE
AS YOU OR I.
NURSE...
IF I GAVE YOU
A DIRECT ORDER
TO BETRAY HIM...
PLEASE.
DON'T ASK ME
TO MAKE THAT CHOICE.
I'D RATHER
YOU PUSH ME OFF
THE SAME PRECIPICE
WHERE MATHEWS DIED.
OH, NO, I CAN'T.
PLEASE,
GO AHEAD AND EAT.
ANDROIDS DON'T EAT,
MISS CHAPEL.
EVEN HAS
YOUR SENSE OF HUMOR.
WELL, THERE'S
ONE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN US--I'M HUNGRY.
THE DIFFERENCE
IS YOUR WEAKNESS,
CAPTAIN, NOT MINE.
ONE AT A TIME,
GENTLEMEN.
CAPTAIN?
EATING IS A PLEASURE,
SIR.
UNFORTUNATELY,
ONE YOU WILL NEVER KNOW.
PERHAPS, BUT I WILL
NEVER STARVE, SIR.
HE'S AN EXACT DUPLICATE?
IN EVERY DETAIL.
WHAT ABOUT MEMORY?
TELL ME ABOUT SAM.
GEORGE SAMUEL KIRK,
YOUR BROTHER.
ONLY YOU CALL HIM SAM.
HE SAW ME OFF
ON THIS MISSION.
YES, WITH HIS WIFE
AND THREE SONS.
HE SAID HE WAS
BEING TRANSFERRED
TO EARTH COLONY 2
RESEARCH STATION.
NO, CAPTAIN. HE SAID HE WAS
CONTINUING HIS RESEARCH
AND THAT HE WANTED
TO BE TRANSFERRED
TO EARTH COLONY 2.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
TRY TO OUTTHINK
A CALCULATING MACHINE.
OBVIOUSLY, I CAN'T...
BUT WE DO HAVE SOME
INTERESTING DIFFERENCES.
TOTALLY
UNIMPORTANT ONES.
YOU MAY LEAVE NOW.
YOU HAVEN'T GUESSED
THE REST, HMM?
NOT EVEN YOU,
CHRISTINE?
WHAT YOU SAW
WAS ONLY A MACHINE,
ONLY HALF OF WHAT I
COULD'VE ACCOMPLISHED,
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
BY CONTINUING THE PROCESS,
I COULD'VE TRANSFERRED YOU,
YOUR VERY CONSCIOUSNESS
INTO THAT ANDROID,
YOUR SOUL, IF YOU WISH.
ALL OF YOU.
IN ANDROID FORM,
A HUMAN BEING CAN HAVE
PRACTICAL IMMORTALITY.
CAN YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M OFFERING MANKIND?
PROGRAMMING.
DIFFERENT WORD, BUT
THE SAME OLD PROMISES
MADE BY GENGHIS KHAN,
JULIUS CAESAR, HITLER,
FERRIS, MALTUVIS.
CAN YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT A HUMAN CONVERTED
TO AN ANDROID
CAN BE PROGRAMMED
FOR THE BETTER?
CAN YOU IMAGINE
HOW LIFE COULD BE IMPROVED
IF WE COULD DO AWAY WITH
JEALOUSY, GREED, HATE?
IT CAN ALSO BE IMPROVED
BY ELIMINATING LOVE,
TENDERNESS, SENTIMENT,
THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE COIN, DOCTOR.
NO ONE
NEED EVER DIE AGAIN.
NO DISEASE,
NO DEFORMITIES,
WHY, EVEN FEAR
CAN BE PROGRAMMED AWAY,
REPLACED WITH JOY.
I'M OFFERING YOU
A PRACTICAL HEAVEN,
A NEW PARADISE,
AND ALL I NEED
IS YOUR HELP.
ALL YOU WANTED BEFORE
WAS MY UNDERSTANDING.
I NEED TRANSPORTATION
TO A PLANET COLONY
WITH PROPER
RAW MATERIALS.
I'M SURE THERE ARE SEVERAL
GOOD POSSIBILITIES
AMONG YOUR NEXT STOPS.
NO DIVERSION
FROM YOUR ROUTE.
I WANT
NO SUSPICIONS AROUSED.
I'LL BEGIN PRODUCING
ANDROIDS CAREFULLY,
SELECTIVELY.
YES.
NO ONE NEED KNOW,
ONLY TO FRIGHTEN
UNINFORMED MINDS.
THEY MUST BE
STRONGLY INFILTRATED
INTO SOCIETY
BEFORE
THE ANDROID EXISTENCE
IS REVEALED.
I WANT NO WAVE
OF HYSTERIA TO DESTROY
WHAT IS GOOD AND RIGHT.
YOU READ ME, CAPTAIN?
YOU'VE CREATED
YOUR OWN KIRK.
WHY DO YOU NEED ME?
I CREATED HIM
TO IMPRESS YOU,
NOT TO REPLACE YOU.
I'M IMPRESSED, DOCTOR...
BUT NOT THE WAY
YOU THINK!
STAND BACK, RUK!
I'LL KILL HIM!
STAY BACK.
RUK...
PROTECT!
ROGER, I...
RUK! NO!
[NURSE CHAPEL]
RUK, STOP!
DR. KORBY SAID
YOU ARE TO OBEY ME!
RUK!
RUK, I ORDER YOU
NOT TO HARM HIM!
[SNAP]
[CHRISTINE'S VOICE]
CAPTAIN KIRK!
WHERE ARE YOU?
I CAN HELP YOU!
CHRISTINE,
IS THAT YOU?
[BOTH GRUNTING]
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN...
WE FINISHED
AHEAD OF SCHEDULE.
DR. KORBY HAS
CONSIDERABLE CARGO
TO BEAM ABOARD.
I'LL HAVE TO GO OVER
OUR DESTINATION
SCHEDULE WITH HIM.
YOU'RE GOING BACK DOWN
WITH THE COMMAND PIKE?
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS,
MR. SPOCK.
I'M SICK OF YOUR
HALF-BREED INTERFERENCE,
DO YOU HEAR?
YES, VERY WELL,
CAPTAIN.
YOU LOOK UPSET,
MR. SPOCK.
IS EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT UP HERE?
NO PROBLEMS HERE, SIR.
GOOD.
I'LL BEAM UP SHORTLY
WITH DR. KORBY
AND PARTY.
SECURITY, SPOCK HERE.
STATUS OF
THE LANDING PARTY.
READY
AND STANDING BY, SIR,
HAVE THEM MEET ME
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
AFTER THE CAPTAIN
HAS BEAMED DOWN.
I LOOKED IT OVER.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
PLANET MIDAS FIVE
AN EXCELLENT CHOICE.
A SMALL COLONY.
ABUNDANT RAW MATERIALS.
YOU MADE
A GOOD BEGINNING,
CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
I FELT QUITE AT HOME
ON THE ENTERPRISE.
ANDREA...
KISS ME.
NO.
NOT PROGRAMMED
FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
ANDREA?
CONFUSED?
NO.
EMOTION, RUK?
YOU DISAPPROVE OF
MISS CHAPEL'S ORDERS
TO SAVE MY LIFE.
TO MAINTAIN
YOUR EXISTENCE
WOULD BE ILLOGICAL.
WHY?
CAN'T YOUR MEMORY BANKS
SOLVE A SIMPLE EQUATION
LIKE THAT?
WHAT HAPPENED...
TO THE OLD ONES,
RUK?
IT'S SO LONG AGO.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THEY BUILT THEIR
MACHINES TOO WELL...
GAVE THEM PRIDE
AND A DESIRE TO SURVIVE?
MACHINES THAT WANTED
LOGIC AND ORDER
AND FOUND THAT
FRUSTRATED
BY THE ILLOGICAL
EMOTIONAL CREATURES
THAT BUILT THEM?
YES.
THE OLD ONES.
THE ONES
WHO MADE US.
THEY GREW FEARFUL
OF US.
THEY BEGAN
TO TURN US OFF.
AND ISN'T IT KORBY
WHO'S CREATING
THE SAME DANGER TO YOU
ALL OVER AGAIN?
UNLIKE YOU,
WE HUMANS ARE FULL OF
UNPREDICTABLE EMOTIONS
THAT LOGIC CANNOT SOLVE.
YES.
YES. IT HAD BEEN
SO LONG AGO,
I HAD FORGOTTEN.
THE OLD ONES HERE.
THE ONES
WHO MADE US, YES.
YES, IT IS STILL
IN MY MEMORY BANKS.
IT BECAME NECESSARY
TO DESTROY THEM.
YOU ARE INCONSISTENT.
YOU CANNOT
BE PROGRAMMED.
YOU ARE INFERIOR.
AND KORBY?
YOU CAME
FROM THE OUTSIDE.
YOU BRING DISORDER HERE.
THE DANGER TO YOU
IS KORBY.
I WAS PROGRAMMED
BY KORBY.
I CANNOT HARM HIM.
THE OLD ONES
PROGRAMMED YOU, TOO,
BUT IT BECAME POSSIBLE
TO DESTROY THEM.
THAT WAS THE EQUATION!
UGH!
EXISTENCE!
SURVIVAL MUST
CANCEL OUT PROGRAMMING.
THAT'S IT, RUK!
LOGIC!
YOU CAN'T
PROTECT SOMEONE
WHO'S TRYING
TO DESTROY YOU!
RUK, I WOULD LIKE--
AH!
YOU BROUGHT HIM AMONG US.
YOU BROUGHT
THE INFERIOR ONES.
WE HAD CLEANSED OURSELVES
OF THEM,
NOW YOU BRING
THE EVIL BACK!
RUK! STOP!
YOUR PROGRAMMING.
I HAD NO CHOICE.
YOU HAD RESPECT
FOR ALL THINGS ALIVE.
HOW CAN I EXPLAIN
THE CHANGE IN YOU?
IF I WAS TO
TELL EARTH THAT
I WAS IN YOUR HANDS--
TELL THEM WHAT HAS
BECOME...
OH!
IT'S STILL ME,
CHRISTINE.
ROGER.
I'M IN HERE.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE
HOW IT WAS.
I WAS FROZEN...
DYING.
MY LEGS WERE GONE.
I WAS...
I HAD ONLY MY BRAIN
BETWEEN LIFE AND DEATH.
THIS CAN BE REPAIRED,
EASIER THAN ANOTHER MAN
CAN SET A BROKEN FINGER.
I'M STILL THE SAME
AS I WAS BEFORE,
CHRISTINE,
PERHAPS EVEN BETTER.
ARE YOU, ROGER?
[ALARM BEEPING]
ANDREA.
YES, DOCTOR.
THERE'S SOMEONE
IN THE OUTER JUNCTION.
SPOCK.
HE MUST'VE
GOT MY MESSAGE.
I WILL FIND RUK.
HE'LL NEVER FIND US
IN THIS MAZE.
RUK HAS BEEN SHUT OFF.
GET A WEAPON.
DEAL WITH IT.
PROTECT.
I WILL KISS YOU.
NO.
YOU...
YOU WILL NOT.
IT IS ILLOGICAL.
I'M THE SAME!
A DIRECT TRANSFER.
ALL OF ME,
HUMAN, RATIONAL,
AND WITHOUT A FLAW.
HE FREED HIMSELF,
AND I DESTROYED--
DESTROYED HIM?
I'M...NOT PROGRAMMED
FOR ALARMS.
I LISTENED
TO YOUR INSTRUCTIONS.
THEY WERE MISSTATED.
SHE KILLED
THE ANDROID, KORBY.
THE SAME WAY
YOU KILLED RUK.
IS THIS
YOUR PERFECT WORLD,
YOUR FLAWLESS BEINGS
KILLING OFF ONE ANOTHER?
AREN'T YOU DOING
EXACTLY WHAT YOU HATE
MOST IN HUMANS,
KILLING WITH NO MORE CONCERN
THAN WHEN YOU TURN OFF
A LIGHT?
I AM NOT A COMPUTER.
TEST ME.
ASK ME TO SOLVE
ANY...
EQUA--
TRANSMI--
CHRISTINE,
LET ME PROVE MYSELF.
DOES THIS MAKE
SUCH A DIFFERENCE?
DON'T YOU SEE, ROGER?
EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE
HAS PROVED IT ISN'T YOU.
I AM ROGER KORBY!
THEN PROVE IT.
GIVE ME THAT PHASER GUN.
IF THERE'S ANY HUMAN
LEFT IN YOU,
GIVE IT TO ME.
NO.
YOU WILL
NEVER UNDERSTAND.
I CONSTRUCTED
A PERFECT BEING,
TESTED IT,
PROVED IT.
ANDREA,
GIVE ME THE WEAPON.
NO. PROTECT.
PROTECT.
TO LOVE YOU.
TO...
KISS YOU.
NO.
YOU CANNOT LOVE.
YOU'RE NOT HUMAN.
LOVE YOU...
KISS...
OH!
CAPTAIN KIRK!
IN HERE, SPOCK.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
NURSE?
WHERE'S DR. KORBY?
DR. KORBY...
WAS NEVER HERE.
THANK YOU
FOR LETTING ME MAKE
THE DECISION, CAPTAIN.
I'M QUITE CERTAIN I'M
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
SHE'S STAYING
WITH THE SHIP.
SOMETHING BOTHERING YOU,
MR. SPOCK?
FRANKLY,
I WAS RATHER DISMAYED
BY YOUR USE OF THE TERM
"HALF-BREED," CAPTAIN.
YOU MUST ADMIT IT IS
AN UNSOPHISTICATED
EXPRESSION.
I'LL REMEMBER THAT,
MR. SPOCK,
THE NEXT TIME I FIND MYSELF
IN A SIMILAR SITUATION.
STEADY AS WE GO, HELM.