EARTH-STYLE
DISTRESS SIGNAL--SOS.
I'VE ANSWERED IT
ON ALL FREQUENCIES, SIR.
THEY DON'T REPLY.
NOT A VESSEL,
A GROUND SOURCE.
THE THIRD PLANET
IN THIS SOLAR SYSTEM,
ACCORDING
TO MY INSTRUMENTS.
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
DEFINITELY AN
EARTH-STYLE SIGNAL.
WE'RE HUNDREDS
OF LIGHT YEARS
FROM EARTH, MR. SPOCK.
NO COLONIES OR VESSELS
OUT THIS FAR.
MEASURING THE PLANET NOW,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S SPHEROID-SHAPED.
CIRCUMFERENCE--
24,874 MILES.
MASS--6 TIMES 10
TO THE 21st POWER TONS.
MEAN DENSITY--5.517.
ATMOSPHERE...
OXYGEN, NITROGEN.
EARTH!
NOT THE EARTH,
ANOTHER EARTH.
ANOTHER EARTH?
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2713.5.
IN THE DISTANT REACHES
OF OUR GALAXY,
WE HAVE MADE
AN ASTONISHING DISCOVERY--
EARTH-TYPE RADIO SIGNALS
COMING FROM A PLANET
WHICH APPARENTLY
IS AN EXACT DUPLICATE
OF THE EARTH.
IT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE...
BUT THERE IT IS.
HOLD US IN A FIXED
ORBIT, MR. SPOCK.
AFFIRMATIVE, CAPTAIN.
STILL NO RESPONSE,
COMMUNICATIONS?
NONE, CAPTAIN.
WE'LL BEAM DOWN.
ALERT SECURITY.
PREPARE TO TRANSPORT
LANDING PARTY
TO SURFACE.
WE'LL LAND
IN THE VICINITY
OF THE DISTRESS SIGNALS
NOW BEING RECEIVED.
IDENTICAL.
EARTH...AS IT WAS
IN THE EARLY 1900s.
MORE THE,
UH, MID-1900s.
I WOULD SAY, CAPTAIN,
APPROXIMATELY 1960.
BUT WHERE IS
EVERYBODY?
READINGS INDICATE THAT
NATURAL DETERIORATION
HAS BEEN TAKING PLACE
ON THIS PLANET
FOR AT LEAST
SEVERAL CENTURIES.
YOU MEAN THERE'S
NO ONE ALIVE?
NOT CONCLUSIVE, YEOMAN.
THE EVIDENCE
WOULD SUGGEST
THAT THE DISTRESS SIGNAL
IS AUTOMATED.
NOW, THIS IS MARVELOUS--
THE MOST HORRIBLE
CONGLOMERATION
OF ANTIQUE ARCHITECTURE
I'VE EVER SEEN.
MR. SPOCK.
[TRICYCLE BELL RINGS]
[WHEEL SQUEAKS]
MINE!
MINE! MINE!
[SOBBING]
IT'S BROKE.
SOMEBODY...BROKE IT.
FIX.
SOMEBODY...PLEASE FIX.
[SOBBING]
OF COURSE SOMEBODY
WILL FIX IT.
DEFINITELY HUMANOID,
IN SPITE OF
THE DISTORTION.
BUT WITH THE MIND
OF A CHILD.
[GASPING]
BONES,
WHAT IS IT?
A SEIZURE
OF SOME TYPE.
WE WANT
TO HELP YOU.
LIAR!
NEVER...NEVER!
NEVER! NEVER!
[LAUGHING]
NEVER!
IT'S DEAD.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
WHAT?
ITS METABOLIC RATE--
IT'S IMPOSSIBLY HIGH,
AS IF IT'S
BURNING ITSELF UP,
ALMOST AS IF
IT AGED A CENTURY
IN JUST THE PAST
FEW MINUTES.
[FOOTSTEPS]
COME ON!
[CREAKING]
HOW OLD IS THIS THING?
ABOUT 300 YEARS.
[THUMPING]
[GROAN]
COME OUT!
WE MEAN YOU NO HARM.
DON'T HURT ME, PLEASE.
I'M NOT
GOING TO HURT YOU.
NO, PLEASE, DON'T.
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I WON'T HURT YOU.
NO, PLEASE, DON'T.
I ONLY WANT TO TALK.
NO, DON'T. DON'T HURT.
COME ON.
DON'T, PLEASE.
I WON'T HURT YOU.
DON'T HURT ME.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
COME ON.
WE WON'T HURT YOU,
SWEETHEART.
WE'RE YOUR FRIENDS.
NO, SHH!
TAKE THE GUARDS.
HAVE A LOOK OUTSIDE.
RADIOACTIVE READINGS,
CHEMICAL POLLUTION,
ANY FURTHER SIGN OF LIFE.
RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
I WONDER WHAT
HAPPENED TO HER
THAT SHE SHOULD
BE SO TERRIFIED OF US.
[TRICORDER WHINES]
BUT I REMEMBER THE THINGS
YOU GRUPS DID--
BURNING, YELLING,
HURTING PEOPLE.
WE DIDN'T
DO ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO HURT?
WELL,
OF COURSE NOT.
WE'RE HERE
TO HELP.
GRUPS DON'T HELP.
BUT WE WILL.
WHAT HAPPENED
HERE?
WHERE IS
EVERYBODY?
YOU KNOW.
NO, I DON'T.
WON'T
YOU TELL ME?
YOU GOT A FOOLIE,
IS THAT IT?
YOU WANT ME
TO PLAY, BUT I CAN'T.
I DON'T KNOW THE RULES.
I'VE GOT TO KNOW THE RULES.
FOOLIE?
A GAME, YOU KNOW.
I CAN'T PLAY A GAME
WITHOUT RULES.
EVEN GRUPS
OUGHT TO KNOW THAT.
WHAT ARE GRUPS?
YOU ARE.
THEY WILL,
WHEN ONLIES GET OLD.
GROWNUPS.
YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT THE...GRUPS
DOING BAD THINGS--
YELLING, HURTING,
BURNING.
THAT WAS WHEN THEY
STARTED TO GET SICK
IN THE BEFORE TIME.
WE HID,
THEN THEY WERE GONE.
AM I DOING ALL RIGHT?
YOU'RE DOING FINE.
YOU SAID THE GRUPS
GOT SICK.
IS THAT WHY
THERE AREN'T ANY
OF THEM AROUND?
YES. THEY DIED,
BUT THAT WAS AFTER
THE AWFUL THINGS.
A PLAGUE, CAPTAIN.
THAT COULD EXPLAIN
A LOT OF IT.
BUT WHAT
ABOUT THE CHILDREN,
THE...ONLIES?
DIDN'T THE AWFUL
THINGS AFFECT THEM?
OF COURSE NOT.
WE'RE HERE, AREN'T WE?
MORE OF YOU?
HOW MANY?
ALL THERE ARE.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
MIRI.
MIRI...
PRETTY NAME...
FOR A PRETTY
YOUNG WOMAN.
PRETTY?
VERY PRETTY.
[BANG]
GUARDS!
COVER ME.
[CHILDREN]
♪ NYAH YAH YAH-YAH YAH ♪
CHILDREN, CAPTAIN,
LOTS OF THEM.
WE COULDN'T BEGIN
TO GET CLOSE TO THEM.
THEY JUST SEEMED
TO SCURRY AWAY...
LIKE ANIMALS.
ONLY CHILDREN.
MIRI SAID
ALL THE ADULTS DIED.
THAT CREATURE
WHICH ATTACKED US
WAS CERTAINLY NO CHILD.
PERHAPS IT DIED
OF THE DISEASE
THE GIRL'S
TALKING ABOUT.
THERE MUST BE
RECORDS SOMEWHERE...
AND ANSWERS TO SOME
OF OUR QUESTIONS.
MIRI...
DO YOU
KNOW ANY BUILDINGS
WHERE THE DOCTORS
USED TO WORK?
YES, I KNOW THAT.
THEM AND THEIR PILLS
AND THINGS.
WILL YOU
TAKE ME THERE?
THAT'S A BAD PLACE.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
PLEASE?
ALL RIGHT.
DO YOU HAVE A NAME, TOO?
YES.
IT'S JIM.
I LIKE THAT NAME.
GOOD.
I LIKE YOURS, TOO.
I LIKE YOU.
DO YOU REALLY?
I WOULDN'T LIE
TO YOU.
TO YOU EITHER, JIM.
I REMEMBER THE GRUPS,
BUT YOU'RE NICE.
YOU'RE DIFFERENT.
WHY, THANK YOU.
IT'S ALREADY STARTING.
I KNEW IT WOULD.
JUST LIKE IT DID
WITH THE GRUPS.
IT'LL SPREAD ALL OVER YOU,
AND YOU'LL YELL.
YOU'LL TRY
TO HURT EVERYBODY.
THEN YOU'LL DIE.
I KNEW IT WOULD!
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2713.6.
THE BUILDING
MIRI LED US TO
ALSO HOUSED AN AUTOMATIC
TRANSMISSION STATION,
WHICH SENT OUT
THE SIGNALS
THAT DREW US
TO THIS PLANET.
WE ALSO DISCOVERED
SOMETHING ELSE--
THAT THE BLUE SPLOTCHES
CHARACTERISTIC
OF THE UNKNOWN DISEASE
HAD APPEARED
ON EACH OF US,
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF MR. SPOCK.
THERE WAS A WELL-EQUIPPED
LABORATORY IN THE BUILDING.
DR. McCOY TOOK TISSUE SAMPLES
OF EACH OF US
IN AN ATTEMPT TO ISOLATE
THE ORGANISM RESPONSIBLE.
A VERITABLE
ZOO OF BACTERIA.
BEAM DOWN
A BIOCOMPUTER
AND A PORTABLE
ELECTRONIC MICROSCOPE.
IF I'M GOING TO BE
DEALING WITH VIRUSES,
I'M GOING TO NEED
BETTER EQUIPMENT
THAN I HAVE HERE.
YES, DOCTOR.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YES, LIEUTENANT?
I'VE GOT VOLUNTEERS
STANDING BY
READY TO HELP YOU, SIR.
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
DO I WANT ANYONE
TO BEAM DOWN FROM THE SHIP.
WE CAN'T TAKE
ANY CHANCES WITH
FURTHER CONTAMINATION.
BUT, CAPTAIN,
IF YOU BECOME TOO ILL--
MY ORDERS STILL STAND,
LIEUTENANT.
YOU CAN HELP US BEST BY
CLEARING THE COMPUTER BANKS
AND STANDING BY.
KIRK OUT.
BONES.
HMM?
WHY DO YOU THINK
THE SYMPTOMS
HAVEN'T APPEARED
IN MR. SPOCK?
I DON'T KNOW.
PROBABLY THE LITTLE BUGS
OR WHATEVER THEY ARE
HAVE NO APPETITE
FOR GREEN BLOOD.
BEING
A RED-BLOODED HUMAN
OBVIOUSLY HAS
ITS DISADVANTAGES.
THERE YOU HAVE
A MUSEUM PIECE, DOCTOR.
LENS TYPE--
MANUALLY OPERATED,
LIGHT-ACTIVATED.
SPARE ME THE ANALYSIS,
MR. SPOCK, PLEASE.
IT IS ENOUGH
THAT IT WORKS.
IT SPREADS
REAL FAST. I KNOW.
WHEN YOU'RE OLD,
IT COVERS YOU
LIKE ANYTHING.
"INTERMEDIATE
EXPERIMENTATION
REPORT PROJECT
ON LIFE..."
"PROLONGATION."
"PROGRESS REPORT--
GENETICS SECTION,
LIFE PROLONGATION PROJECT."
THAT'S WHAT IT WAS.
LIFE PROLONGATION.
DIDN'T HAVE
MUCH LUCK, DID THEY?
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
DR. McCOY'S BIOCOMPUTER
AND A PORTABLE
ELECTRONIC MICROSCOPE
HAVE BEEN BEAMED DOWN
FROM THE ENTERPRISE.
THEY WILL BE
USED IN CONJUNCTION
WITH COMPUTER BANKS
ON-BOARD SHIP.
TUBULAR WITH
EXTREME MULTIPLICABILITY.
APPEAR TO HAVE AFFINITY
FOR NUCLEIC ACIDS...
THIS WAS
300 YEARS AGO, CAPTAIN.
ALL THE ADULTS ARE DEAD.
ONLY THE CHILDREN
ARE LEFT ALIVE.
BUT CHILDREN
BECOME ADULTS.
AT LEAST...
THEY HAVE UP TO NOW.
DOCTOR?
THERE ARE CERTAIN
GLANDULAR CHANGES
WHICH TAKE PLACE
UPON ENTERING PUBERTY,
ARE THERE NOT?
OF COURSE.
IT CHANGES THE ENTIRE
BODY SYSTEM.
YOU KNOW THAT.
OF COURSE YOU KNOW THAT.
WHY?
IS IT NOT POSSIBLE
THAT THESE CHILDREN HERE,
AS THEY ENTER PUBERTY,
CONTRACT THE DISEASE?
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN
WHY THERE ARE
NO ADULTS.
GLANDULAR...
POSTPUBESCENT.
IT COULD BE.
IT'S ILLOGICAL.
IT DOES NOT FOLLOW.
ALL THE ADULTS
ON THIS PLANET DIED
300 YEARS AGO,
BUT THERE ARE CHILDREN
IN THE STREETS.
WHO DIE WHEN THEY
ENTER ADOLESCENCE.
BUT...HOW DO THEY
KEEP THE LINE GOING?
ONE THING, CAPTAIN.
IF SHE WERE
A WILD ANIMAL
EVER SINCE SHE'S
BEEN A LITTLE GIRL,
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
THAT SHE WANTS
TO STAY WITH US?
LONELINESS.
I DON'T KNOW.
CURIOSITY.
I THINK
CHILDREN HAVE
AN INSTINCTIVE NEED
FOR ADULTS.
THEY WANT TO BE TOLD
RIGHT AND WRONG.
THERE MAY BE
OTHER EMOTIONS AT WORK
IN THIS CASE, CAPTAIN.
[McCOY]
SHE LIKES YOU, JIM.
SHE'S BECOMING
A WOMAN.
MR. SPOCK.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
SPOCK HERE.
HERE ARE THOSE FIGURES
YOU ASKED FOR.
12 TO THE 10th POWER.
METABOLIC RATE--72%.
PRODUCTION
OF NUCLEIC ACIDS
REDUCED
TO 33% OF NORMAL.
CONVENTIONAL
CHRONOLOGICAL
PROGRESSION--100 x 3.6.
ACKNOWLEDGED, LIEUTENANT.
I HAVE
THE CALCULATIONS NOW.
TRY AGAIN.
SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND ANYTHING OUTSIDE.
HEY...CLEAN UP THAT DESK
FOR ME, WILL YOU?
ALL RIGHT, JIM.
ACCORDING TO THEIR
LIFE PROLONGATION PLAN,
WHAT THEY THOUGHT
THEY WERE ACCOMPLISHING,
A PERSON WOULD
AGE ONLY ONE MONTH
FOR EVERY 100 YEARS
OF REAL TIME.
100 YEARS
AND ONLY ONE MONTH?
EXACTLY, YEOMAN.
EVIDENTLY THROUGH
SOME MISCALCULATION,
THIS VIRUS ANNIHILATED
THE ENTIRE ADULT POPULATION
IN A VERY SHORT PERIOD,
LEAVING
ONLY THE CHILDREN.
BUT THAT MEANS
THESE CHILDREN...
COULD VERY WELL
BE IMMENSELY OLD.
THAT WOULD CERTAINLY
ANSWER THE QUESTION
OF WHAT HAPPENED
TO THEIR PARENTS.
ANSWERS IT VERY WELL.
CHILDREN
WHO NEVER AGE...
ETERNAL CHILDHOOD,
FILLED WITH PLAY...
NO RESPONSIBILITIES.
IT'S ALMOST
LIKE A DREAM.
I WOULDN'T
EXAMINE THAT DREAM
TOO CLOSELY, YEOMAN.
IT MIGHT NOT
TURN OUT TO BE
VERY PRETTY.
A FEW DAYS AGO
OR A WEEK AGO
THAT CREATURE
THAT ATTACKED US
COULD HAVE BEEN
JUST LIKE MIRI.
A CHILD ENTERING PUBERTY
ON THIS PLANET
MEANS A DEATH SENTENCE.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
SHE KNOWS?
I DON'T THINK SO.
IF THEY'RE AS OLD
AS SPOCK CLAIMS,
THEY MUST HAVE SOME IDEA
OF WHAT'S HAPPENING.
THERE'S NO ADULT
INTERPRETATION.
I THINK
WE'RE DEALING
WITH CHILDREN,
IMMENSELY OLD
PERHAPS,
BUT NONETHELESS
CHILDREN.
WE'VE GOT
TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THE OTHERS.
DIFFICULT.
WE CAN'T EVEN GET
A GLIMPSE OF THEM.
YOU COULDN'T
GET CLOSE
TO THE OTHER KIDS?
IMPOSSIBLE.
THEY KNOW THE AREA
TOO WELL,
LIKE MICE.
I'M GOING TO TRY.
MIRI?
COME HERE.
YOU WANT TO GO
SOMEPLACE WITH ME?
SURE.
THAT LITTLE GIRL...
IS AT LEAST
300 YEARS OLDER
THAN YOU ARE, YEOMAN.
THINK ABOUT IT.
MIRI IS WITH THEM!
WHY?
WHAT'S SHE GOING
TO DO, JAHN?
I DON'T--I DON'T KNOW.
I KNOW WHAT
WE'VE GOT TO DO.
THERE ARE MORE OF THEM
THAN WE SEE.
SOMEWHERE...
UP IN THE SKY...
MAYBE, SOMEWHERE.
THEY TALK TO EACH OTHER
ALL THE TIME.
YOU KNOW GRUPS.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY DO--
THE HURTING, THE KILLING.
I REMEMBER, JAHN,
THE WAY IT WAS.
THAT'S RIGHT,
THE WAY IT WAS
IN THE BEFORE TIME.
THEY TALK TO
THE OTHER GRUPS
WITH THESE LITTLE BOXES.
NOW, IF THEY DIDN'T HAVE
THOSE LITTLE BOXES,
THEY'D BE...ALL ALONE.
HUH?
BUT THEY
DON'T SEE US.
WE HIDE.
OLLY OLLY OXEN FREE!
NO!
IT'S NOT A GAME.
IT'S REAL.
THEY'RE DANGEROUS.
THEY'RE GRUPS.
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
JAHN!
All right!
Let's hide!
[THUMP]
[CHILDREN SCREAM]
AAH!
DEAD.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
MY PHASER WASN'T
SET TO KILL.
HER NAME WAS LOUISE.
SHE WAS JUST
A LITTLE BIT OLDER
THAN I AM
WHEN IT HAPPENED.
OH, JIM.
DATA HAS BEEN FED
INTO THE COMPUTERS,
MR. SPOCK.
STAND BY.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
ARE THESE ENOUGH, JIM?
WE COULD USE MORE,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
NO, I DON'T MIND.
THERE COULDN'T BE
ANY DOUBT ABOUT
WHAT YOU FOUND HERE?
THIS FELLOW
MADE THESE NOTES
IN THE LAST WEEKS
AFTER THE DISASTER BEGAN.
I DISREGARD
THESE LAST ENTRIES.
HE SAID HIMSELF
HE WAS TOO SICK,
TOO FAR GONE
TO BE SURE HE WASN'T
ALREADY MAD, AND I AGREE,
BUT BASED ON THE ENTRIES
HE MADE BEFORE THAT,
I KNOW
HOW MUCH TIME WE HAVE.
THE SHIP'S COMPUTERS
WILL VERIFY MY FIGURES.
ONLY A MATTER OF TIME
BEFORE WE ALL GO MAD,
DESTROY EACH OTHER,
TILL THE LAST OF US
FINALLY DESTROYS
HIMSELF.
WHAT ABOUT MIRI?
OUR GUESS WAS CORRECT.
THEY CONTRACT THE DISEASE
AS THEY ENTER PUBERTY
AND THEIR METABOLISM
CHANGES.
THE NOTES INDICATE
IT DOESN'T BECOME ACUTE
FOR A MONTH OR SO.
I ESTIMATE SHE HAS PERHAPS
FIVE OR SIX WEEKS LEFT.
WHAT ABOUT US?
THE OLDER THE VICTIM,
THE MORE RAPID THE PROGRESS
OF THE DISEASE.
AND YOU?
THE DISEASE DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE INTERESTED IN YOU.
I AM A CARRIER.
WHATEVER HAPPENS,
I CAN'T GO BACK
TO THE SHIP,
AND I DO WANT TO GO
BACK TO THE SHIP, CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE, MR. SPOCK.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT WE'RE FIGHTING.
NO...BUT WE KNOW
WHAT IT IS AND
HOW FAST IT DOES IT.
IT'S PROGRESSING.
WE'LL BEGIN TO FEEL IT
INSIDE SOON--
INTENSE FEVER,
GREAT PAIN
IN THE EXTREMITIES,
FUZZINESS OF VISION.
OF COURSE, THOSE ARE
THE EARLY SYMPTOMS.
THERE'LL BE MORE.
ARE YOU CERTAIN
ABOUT THE TIME
WE HAVE LEFT?
I PRESUME MY CALCULATIONS
ARE CORRECT.
IS THERE
ANY POSSIBILITY--
LANDING PARTY,
THIS IS THE ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE.
COMPUTER INDICATES
170 HOURS, MR. SPOCK.
VERIFIED, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE SEVEN DAYS.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENT--
THIS IS THE SECOND DAY
OF THE SEVEN LEFT TO US.
WE'VE FOUND NOTHING.
ENTERPRISE
IS STANDING BY
WITH LABS AND COMPUTERS
READY TO ASSIST US.
THERE'S NO DATA,
NO STOPPING POINT.
I THINK I'VE FOUND IT.
JANICE,
TAKE MIRI FOR A WALK.
YES, SIR.
ONLY ONE HALF INTACT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THEY WERE UP TO?
MORE OR LESS.
THE IDEA WAS TO CREATE
A NEW SERIES OF DISEASES--
A CHAIN REACTION
OF VIRUSES
MEANT ESSENTIALLY
TO EXTEND THE LIFE
OF THE HUMAN CELL
IMMEASURABLY.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THEY WEREN'T SUCCESSFUL.
WE'VE SEEN THE RESULTS.
YOU TWO WILL HAVE TO
RECREATE THEIR THINKING.
IF YOU CAN ISOLATE
THAT VIRUS,
WE'LL BE ABLE
TO DEVELOP A VACCINE.
IS THAT ALL, CAPTAIN?
WE HAVE FIVE DAYS,
YOU KNOW.
I KNOW.
[CHILDREN'S VOICES]
♪ NYAH YAH YAH-YAH YAH ♪
THE CHILDREN.
ANYTHING?
NO, NOTHING.
AND YOU?
[GRATE CLOSES]
COMMUNICATORS, CAPTAIN...
THEY'RE GONE.
JIM, WE'VE ABSOLUTELY
GOT TO HAVE
THOSE COMMUNICATORS.
WITHOUT THEM,
WE DON'T HAVE THE COMPUTERS,
AND WITHOUT THE COMPUTERS,
WE DON'T HAVE A CHANCE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2717.3--
THREE DAYS, SEVEN HOURS
LEFT TO US.
INVESTIGATION PROVES
THAT THE SUPPLY OF FOOD
IN THE AREA
IS RUNNING
DANGEROUSLY LOW.
UNLESS SOMETHING
IS DONE,
THE CHILDREN WILL STARVE
IN A FEW MONTHS.
IN ADDITION, THE DISEASE
IS WORKING ON EACH OF US
ACCORDING
TO DR. McCOY'S PREDICTION.
OUR TEMPERS
ARE GROWING SHORT.
AND WE'RE NO FURTHER ALONG
THAN WE WERE TWO DAYS AGO.
HAVEN'T YOU FOUND
A THING YET?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TAKE A CRACK AT IT?
[GLASS BREAKS]
NO!
I'M UPSET, CAPTAIN,
SO UPSET.
BACK ON THE SHIP,
I USED TO TRY TO GET YOU
TO LOOK AT MY LEGS.
CAPTAIN...
LOOK AT MY LEGS.
WE'RE ALL FRIGHTENED.
[McCOY]
JIM, I FOUND
SOMETHING!
THE LAST SLIDE
I EXAMINED,
I FAILED TO MAKE
THE NECESSARY ADJUSTMENT.
THE SLOWING DOWN
OF MY OWN RESPONSES--
NEVER MIND THAT,
WHAT DID YOU FIND?
THE DISEASE--
THE ONE THEY CREATED
300 YEARS AGO.
THERE'S
A CHANCE!
A CHANCE.
AT LEAST
IT'S A RACE NOW,
AND WE'VE JUST
WASTED A MINUTE.
THAT WOULD BE
SOME FOOLIE, MIRI,
BUT DO YOU THINK
IT WOULD WORK?
I KNOW. I KNOW.
DON'T YOU THINK
I'VE HEARD THEM TALK?
THEY HAVE
SUCH LITTLE TIME
TO DO THIS DUMB THING
OF THEIRS--
THIS BANINSKI THING.
IF WE GET HER AWAY--
THAT YEOMAN--
THAT'S ONE PERSON LESS
TO START OFF WITH.
BUT HOW, MIRI,
IF THEY'RE SO BUSY,
IF THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE
THE BIG EMERGENCY,
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO GET HER AWAY?
IT'S EASY.
SHE'S ALWAYS ASKING ME
ABOUT THE YOUNGEST ONLIES--
THE LITTLE ONES.
"WHAT IF THEY GET SICK,
WHO TAKES CARE OF THEM?
"DO THEY HAVE ENOUGH
TO EAT?
WHERE DO THEY SLEEP?"
I'LL JUST TELL HER
ONE OF YOU FELL DOWN
AND GOT HURT.
ME. SAY IT'S ME.
ALL RIGHT. YOU.
BUT GRUPS--
THEY KNOW THINGS
AND ALL THAT.
YOU KNOW, I BET THEY'LL
BE ABLE TO DO IT
WITH ONE PERSON LESS.
NOT ONE--
TWO.
BECAUSE HE'LL TRY
TO FIND HER.
WHO?
WHO WILL, MIRI?
THE CAPTAIN.
HE'LL TRY TO FIND HER,
BUT HE WON'T...
MR. LOVEY-DOVEY.
LOVEY-DOVEY--
BUNK BUNK
ON THE HEAD.
BUNK BUNK!
IT LOOKS RIGHT.
THE NITROGEN CYCLE?
IT HAS TO BE.
YEAH, BUT THE QUESTION
IS--WHAT'S THE DOSAGE?
HMM.
THAT IS A VERY GOOD
QUESTION.
WHERE IS SHE, MIRI?
WHERE'S JANICE?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
HOW SHOULD I KNOW?
WHERE IS SHE?
HAS SOMETHING
HAPPENED TO HER?
DON'T YOU FEEL
ALL RIGHT?
NO, I DON'T
FEEL ALL RIGHT!
NONE OF US FEEL ALL RIGHT!
CAN'T YOU SEE
WHAT'S GOING ON?
JIM, I DON'T WANT
ANYTHING TO HAPPEN
TO YOU.
I'VE GOT TO FIND JANICE.
THAT'S NOT ALL, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND
THOSE COMMUNICATORS.
WE'RE TRYING, MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE TRYING VERY HARD.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH!
THIS COULD BE IT,
BUT WE CAN'T TEST IT
WITHOUT THE SHIP'S
COMPUTERS.
WE'VE GOT TO HAVE
THOSE COMMUNICATORS, JIM.
THIS IS THE VACCINE?
THAT'S WHAT
THE COMPUTERS
WILL TELL US.
WITHOUT THEM,
IT COULD BE A BEAKER
FULL OF DEATH.
DID YOU HEAR THEM?
WE ONLY HAVE
A FEW HOURS LEFT.
I DON'T CARE.
YOU'VE GOT TO CARE.
MIRI...
I'M GOING TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
YOU, YOUR FRIENDS,
ALL THE ONLIES,
ARE GOING
TO GET THE DISEASE
UNLESS WE SUCCEED
IN WHAT WE'RE DOING.
YOU'VE SEEN SOME
YOUR FRIENDS GET IT.
SOMETIMES IT HAPPENS.
NOT SOMETIMES.
ALL THE TIMES, MIRI!
AS SOON AS YOU
START GROWING UP
THE WAY YOU ARE...
DON'T YOU KNOW
WHY YOU DON'T LIKE
TO PLAY GAMES ANYMORE,
WHY YOU DON'T
SEE YOUR FRIENDS
THE WAY YOU USED TO?
IT'S BECAUSE
YOU'RE BECOMING
A YOUNG WOMAN...
AND THE MOMENT YOU
BECOME A YOUNG WOMAN,
YOU GET THE DISEASE--
ALL OF YOU.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
IT JUST HAPPENS SOMETIMES.
ALL THE TIME, MIRI!
IT'S HAPPENING TO YOU
RIGHT NOW!
LOOK AT IT!
LOOK AT IT, MIRI,
IT'S IN YOU!
NO!
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH!
NO, YOU GOT THE WRONG GAME--
A TEACHER,
I TOLD YOU!
NOW, WHAT DOES
A TEACHER SAY, HUH?
YEAH.
STUDY, STUDY, STUDY,
OR BUNK BUNK,
BAD KID.
IT'S NOT FUNNY.
IT'S A FOOLIE.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO WITH ME?
YOU THINK I'D TELL YOU?
[DOOR OPENS]
MIRI.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE.
I KNOW.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
SOMETHING GO WRONG?
NO.
OK, THEN.
JUST DON'T STAND THERE
IN THE DOORWAY.
COME ON IN.
LISTEN TO HIM.
YOU LISTEN, MIRI.
I DID.
WHY DO YOU THINK
I BROUGHT HIM HERE?
TELL THEM, JIM.
"TELL THEM, JIM."
TELL THEM, JIM!
LISTEN TO ME.
LISTEN TO ME!
NO YELLING
IN THE CLASSROOM!
LOOK AT HIM--
A VERY BAD CITIZEN.
THIS ISN'T A GAME.
IT NEVER WAS A GAME.
CALL THE POLICE!
I'M THE POLICE.
BUNK BUNK
UNLESS YOU'RE GOOD.
YOU'RE THE TEACHER.
I GOT TWO JOBS.
BUNK BUNK!
[CHILDREN]
BLAH BLAH BLAH!
LISTEN TO ME!
YOU'VE GOT
OUR COMMUNICATORS--
THE BOXES WE TALK INTO.
WE NEED THEM
TO TALK TO THE SHIP.
BLAH BLAH BLAH!
NO BLAH BLAH BLAH!
BECAUSE IF WE DON'T
TALK TO THE SHIP,
IF YOU DON'T HELP US...
THERE WON'T BE
ANY GAMES ANYMORE.
THERE WON'T BE ANYTHING...
NOTHING--
NO GRUPS, NO ONLIES,
NOBODY LEFT...
FOREVER AND EVER.
CAPTAIN.
NOW, LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'VE GOT TO HELP US
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
LET JANICE GO.
GIVE ME
THOSE COMMUNICATORS
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
♪ NYAH YAH YAH-YAH YAH ♪
YOU'VE SEEN YOUR FRIENDS
CHANGE ONE BY ONE
AS THEY GREW UP.
DID YOU EVER SEE
ONE OF THEM NOT CHANGE?
ONE BY ONE,
THEY GOT THE DISEASE,
AND THEY BECAME LIKE--
LIKE THOSE CREATURES
YOU'RE AFRAID OF--
LIKE LOUISE.
ONE BY ONE THEY CHANGED
AND GOT THE DISEASE.
THE DISEASE LIKE I'VE GOT,
LIKE MIRI HAS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT?
YOU'RE NOT BABIES.
WE CAN HELP YOU!
BUNK BUNK!
NO, PLEASE. NO!
IT'S WAITING FOR YOU.
IT MAY BE ONLY
A MATTER OF MONTHS.
LISTEN TO HIM.
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
HE'S FUNNY.
HE THINKS HE'S FUNNY.
BUNK BUNK!
GET HIM!
LOOK AT MY ARMS!
THAT'S WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO YOU...
UNLESS YOU LET ME HELP YOU.
BUNK BUNK!
AND THE LITTLE ONES...
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
TO THEM AFTER YOU'VE GONE,
AFTER YOU'VE TURNED
INTO CREATURES LIKE LOUISE?
THEY'LL STILL BE HERE,
BUT NOT FOR LONG,
BECAUSE THE FOOD'S
ALL GONE.
YOU'VE EATEN IT.
MAYBE SIX MONTHS LEFT,
THAT'S ALL,
AND THEN NOTHING LEFT
TO EAT,
NOBODY LEFT
TO TAKE CARE OF THEM.
THEY'LL DIE, TOO.
LOOK AT MY ARM, JAHN.
IT'S HAPPENING TO ME.
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH.
THEY'RE GRUPS!
BUNK BUNK!
ALL RIGHT,
YOU WANT A FOOLIE?
ALL RIGHT.
I DARE YOU.
I DOUBLE-DARE YOU.
LOOK AT THE BLOOD
ON MY FACE.
NOW LOOK AT YOUR HANDS.
BLOOD ON YOUR HANDS.
NOW WHO'S DOING
THE HURTING?
NOT THE GRUPS.
IT'S YOU HURTING, YELLING,
MAYBE KILLING,
JUST LIKE THE GRUPS
YOU REMEMBER
AND CREATURES
YOU'RE AFRAID OF.
YOU'RE ACTING LIKE THEM,
AND YOU'RE GOING TO BE
JUST LIKE THEM
UNLESS YOU
LET ME HELP YOU.
I'M A GRUP.
AND I WANT TO HELP YOU.
I'M BEGGING YOU.
LET ME HELP YOU,
OR THERE WON'T BE
ANYTHING LEFT AT ALL.
PLEASE.
WE CAN'T WAIT
FOR THOSE COMMUNICATORS
ANY LONGER.
WE MUST. THE VACCINE
COULD BE FATAL.
THE DISEASE
CERTAINLY IS.
HOW LONG
DO WE HAVE LEFT--
HOURS, MINUTES?
HOW MUCH LONGER
DO YOU WANT TO WAIT?
BICKERING IS POINTLESS.
I'LL CHECK ON
THE CAPTAIN'S PROGRESS.
SPOCK!
IS HE DEAD, MR. SPOCK?
NOT YET.
3 HOURS,
11 MINUTES LEFT.
THANK YOU,
LIEUTENANT.
KEEP THIS CHANNEL OPEN.
CLEAR YOUR COMPUTERS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO McCOY?
HE INJECTED HIMSELF
WITH THE VACCINE.
HE WAS UNCONSCIOUS
WHEN I FOUND HIM.
LOOK AT HIS FACE.
THE BLEMISHES ARE FADING.
[SPOCK]
THEY'RE FADING.
I NEVER WILL UNDERSTAND
THE MEDICAL MIND.
IS THIS SUPPOSED TO BE
A GOOD THING, MIRI?
OF COURSE IT IS.
THEY WERE JUST CHILDREN.
SIMPLY
TO LEAVE THEM THERE
WITH A MEDICAL TEAM--
JUST CHILDREN--
300 YEARS OLD AND MORE.
I'VE ALREADY CONTACTED
SPACE CENTRAL.
THEY'LL SEND
TEACHERS, ADVISERS.
AND TRUANT OFFICERS,
I PRESUME.
THEY'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
MIRI--
SHE REALLY LOVED YOU,
YOU KNOW.
YES.
I NEVER GET INVOLVED
WITH OLDER WOMEN, YEOMAN.
MR. SPOCK?
CAPTAIN?
FULL AHEAD.
WARP FACTOR 1.
WARP FACTOR 1, CAPTAIN.