READY TO BEAM DOWN.
ENERGIZE.
HAVING TROUBLE,
GENTLEMEN?
I JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE PROBLEM, SIR.
YOU'RE BEAMING CARGO DOWN
TO A PENAL COLONY,
MR. BERKELEY.
THEIR SECURITY
FORCE FIELD, SIR.
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
TANTALUS COLONY.
Woman: REHAB COLONY.
COME IN.
REQUEST OPENING
IN YOUR FORCE FIELD
FOR BEAMING DOWN
OF CARGO.
ENTERPRISE,
AFFIRMATIVE.
OUR SECURITY COVER
IS NOW OPEN.
ENERGIZE.
ANY INCOMING CARGO?
JUST ONE ITEM, SIR--
SOME RESEARCH MATERIAL
BOUND FOR
THE CENTRAL BUREAU
OF PENOLOGY, STOCKHOLM.
Woman: TANTALUS CARGO
READY TO BEAM UP.
OH, MR. BERKELEY,
YOU MIGHT
REFAMILIARIZE YOURSELF
WITH THE MANUAL ON
PENAL COLONY PROCEDURES.
IMMEDIATELY, SIR.
I THINK
YOU CAN TAKE THE TIME
TO LOCK THIS UP FIRST.
I'LL GET
A VAULT ASSIGNMENT.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION...
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2715.1.
EXCHANGED CARGO WITH
PENAL COLONY ON TANTALUS 5.
I'VE DEPARTED
WITHOUT GOING ASHORE.
I WOULD LIKE TO
HAVE MET DR. ADAMS.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
TO A PENAL COLONY
SINCE THEY STARTED
FOLLOWING HIS THEORIES?
A CAGE IS A CAGE, JIM.
YOU'RE BEHIND
THE TIMES, BONES.
THEY'RE MORE LIKE
RESORT COLONIES NOW.
Uhura:
MESSAGE, CAPTAIN.
SWITCHING
TO SPEAKER.
Woman:
TANTALUS COLONY
TO ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE UNABLE TO LOCATE
ONE OF OUR INMATES.
THIS IS A POTENTIALLY
VIOLENT CASE.
POSSIBLY HIDDEN IN THE BOX
WE BEAMED UP TO YOU.
REPEAT, UNABLE TO LOCATE
ONE OF OUR INMATES.
THIS IS A POTENTIALLY
VIOLENT CASE.
ENTERPRISE ACKNOWLEDGING.
STAND BY.
SECURITY ALERT 3.
SECURITY ALERT.
CONDITION 3.
ALL SECTIONS GO
TO ALERT CONDITION 3.
WE MAY HAVE
AN INTRUDER ABOARD.
REPEAT, ALL SECTIONS
TO ALERT CONDITION 3.
INTRUDER ABOARD.
HEY...YOU
FROM ENGINEERING!
BRIDGE, SECTION C,
DECK 14.
CAPTAIN,
SECTION C, DECK 14,
REPORTING TROUBLE.
SOMEONE IN
ENGINEERING UNIFORM.
SECURITY CONTROL,
THIS IS THE BRIDGE.
COME IN.
I HAVE THEM, CAPTAIN.
CLOSING OFF DECK 14.
SEARCH IN PROGRESS.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
Uhura:
SECURITY ALERT,
CONDITION 3.
APPROXIMATELY 6'4", MALE,
EARLY FORTIES.
APPROACH WITH CAUTION.
THIS MAN
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
REPEAT, APPROACH
WITH EXTREME CAUTION.
BRIDGE OUT.
NEGATIVE IN
THE DECK AREA, CAPTAIN.
HE MAY HAVE GOTTEN OUT.
EXPANDING SEARCH
TO ADJOINING SECTIONS.
ENTERPRISE TO
TANTALUS COLONY.
ADAMS HERE.
DR. ADAMS?
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
IT APPEARS WE MAY HAVE
AN INMATE OF YOURS
ABOARD THE SHIP.
TRANSPORTER CREWMAN
FOUND UNCONSCIOUS, CAPTAIN.
CARGO CASE OPEN AND EMPTY.
MAKE THAT DEFINITE, DOCTOR.
HE'S ABOARD.
Dr. Adams:
TERRIBLY SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I TAKE ALL THE BLAME.
LET ME REPEAT,
HE'S CLEVER AS WELL AS
EXTREMELY VIOLENT.
TAKE ALL
POSSIBLE PRECAUTIONS.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED,
DOCTOR. KIRK OUT.
Man: ALL SECTIONS,
SECURITY CHECK
IN PROGRESS. REPORT.
FORWARD PHASER,
AFFIRMATIVE.
[INDISTINCT
CHATTERING]
SECTION OPERATIONAL
READY.
INTERESTING.
YOUR EARTH PEOPLE
GLORIFY ORGANIZED VIOLENCE
FOR 40 CENTURIES,
BUT YOU IMPRISON THOSE
WHO EMPLOY IT PRIVATELY.
AND, OF COURSE,
YOUR PEOPLE
FOUND AN ANSWER.
WE DISPOSED
OF EMOTION, DOCTOR.
WHERE THERE IS
NO EMOTION...
THERE IS NO MOTIVE
FOR VIOLENCE.
[DOORS OPEN]
WHERE'S THE CAPTAIN?
WHICH ONE OF YOU
IS THE CAPTAIN?
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
MY NAME IS...
VAN GELDER.
I WANT ASYLUM.
AT GUNPOINT?
I WANT
YOUR PROMISE FIRST,
YOUR WORD THAT YOU WON'T
TAKE ME BACK THERE--
TO TANTALUS.
NO PROMISES.
GIVE ME THE WEAPON.
NO!
NO...
NO, I'M NOT GOING BACK!
I'LL DISABLE
YOUR VESSEL FIRST.
YOU CHOOSE, CAPTAIN.
I'LL DESTROY
YOUR CONTROL PANEL.
TAKE HIM TO SICK BAY.
REVERSE COURSE.
HEAD BACK
FOR TANTALUS COLONY.
ABNORMAL, OF COURSE.
IT'S NOT
SCHIZOPHRENIA...
TISSUE DAMAGE...
OR ANY CONDITION
I'M ACQUAINTED WITH, JIM.
YOU KNOW,
AFTER GETTING HIM HERE,
IT TOOK ALMOST
A TRIPLE DOSE OF SEDATIVE
TO PUT HIM UNDER.
THE REPORT SAID
HE WAS QUITE TALKATIVE.
BUT NOT
VERY INFORMATIVE.
HE CLAIMED ONE THING,
THEN HE SEEMED TO FORGET.
AND THEN,
HE'D START TO CLAIM
SOMETHING ELSE.
BUT ALWAYS WITH
JUST THE RING
OF TRUTH IN IT.
I'D SURE LIKE TO
STUDY THIS ONE, JIM.
IT'S NOT OUR PROBLEM,
BONES.
YOU SMART,
BUTTON-PUSHING
BRASS HAT.
WASH YOUR HANDS
OF IT.
IS THAT YOUR SYSTEM?
YOU'RE BOTH QUITE
SURE OF YOURSELVES,
AREN'T YOU?
QUITE EXPERT.
TAKE HIM BACK.
LET SOMEONE ELSE
WORRY ABOUT HIM.
WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS?
MY NAME?
MY NAME IS--AAH--
SIMON...
VAN GELDER.
I WAS THE DIRECTOR OF--
[GROANS]
DIRECTOR...
AT THE...
TANTALUS COLONY.
YOU SEE WHAT I MEAN?
I WAS A GRADUATE OF...
OF...
I WAS ASSISTANT TO...
TO...
DOCTOR...
AAH!
AAH...
I KNEW...
I KNEW.
BUT
THEY'VE ERASED IT.
ERASED?
EDITED...
ADJUSTED...
SUBVERTED ME.
BUT I WON'T FORGET!
I WON'T FORGET!
YOU...YOU'RE SO
BLIND IGNORANT.
YOU BELIEVE I BELONG
BACK THERE, DON'T YOU?
DEAD OR ALIVE.
WELL, I WON'T LET YOU
TAKE ME BACK!
I'M NOT GOING!
I'LL DIE FIRST!
DO YOU HEAR?
I'M NOT GOING!
NO!
NO...
[HYPOSPRAY HISSES]
ESTIMATING ARRIVAL
AT TANTALUS?
57 MINUTES,
30 SECONDS, CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S SO FASCINATING?
AN IDENTIFICATION TAPE
FROM OUR SHIP'S LIBRARY
ON DR. SIMON VAN GELDER.
DR. VAN GELDER?
DR. VAN GELDER,
CAPTAIN.
NO MISTAKE.
THERE'S A FULL
I.D. TAPE ON HIM.
COMMITTED TO
TANTALUS COLONY WHEN?
ASSIGNED THERE,
SIX MONTHS AGO,
AS DR. ADAMS'
ASSOCIATE.
SHIP TO SURFACE,
TANTALUS COLONY.
Uhura:
HAILING FREQUENCY'S
OPEN, SIR.
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
TO TANTALUS COLONY.
Woman:
TANTALUS.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
I'D LIKE TO SPEAK
TO DR. ADAMS.
STAND BY,
ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
DR. ADAMS HERE.
DR. ADAMS, REGARDING
YOUR ESCAPED MAN--
IS DR. VAN GELDER
ALL RIGHT?
AND YOUR PEOPLE--
NO INJURIES?
NO CASUALTIES, SIR.
THIS MAN IS...
DR. SIMON VAN GELDER?
YES, OF COURSE.
YOU'RE CERTAIN
HE'S ALL RIGHT?
WE'VE BEEN
VERY CONCERNED.
IN THE VIOLENT STATE
HE'S IN--
NO HARM TO HIM, SIR.
WE THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
ENLIGHTEN US
AS TO HIS CONDITION.
HE'D BEEN DOING
SOME EXPERIMENTAL WORK,
CAPTAIN,
AN EXPERIMENTAL BEAM
WE'D HOPED
MIGHT REHABILITATE
INCORRIGIBLES.
VAN GELDER FELT HE
HADN'T THE MORAL RIGHT
TO EXPOSE ANOTHER MAN
TO SOMETHING
HE HADN'T TRIED
ON HIS OWN PERSON.
TRAGEDY, DOCTOR.
JIM...
THAT DOESN'T
QUITE RING TRUE.
UH, DR. ADAMS...
PLEASE STAND BY.
EXPLAIN.
I DON'T BELIEVE HIM.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT,
BUT THE MORE
I STUDY THAT PATIENT--
YOU DON'T BELIEVE HIM
AND YOU CAN'T
EXPLAIN IT.
BONES, ARE YOU AWARE
THAT IN THE LAST
20 YEARS,
DR. ADAMS HAS DONE MORE
TO REVOLUTIONIZE,
TO HUMANIZE PRISONS
AND THE TREATMENT
OF PRISONERS
THAN ALL THE REST
OF HUMANITY HAD DONE
IN 40 CENTURIES?
I'VE BEEN TO
THOSE PENAL COLONIES
SINCE THEY'VE BEGUN
FOLLOWING HIS METHODS.
AND THEY'RE
NOT CAGES ANYMORE.
McCoy:
JIM...
THEY'RE CLEAN,
DECENT HOSPITALS
FOR SICK MINDS.
JIM, LISTEN.
GENTLEMEN...
I SUGGEST
YOU ASK DR. ADAMS
IF HE WANTS
VAN GELDER RETURNED.
DR. ADAMS...
REGARDING VAN GELDER...
YES, CAPTAIN.
MAY I INQUIRE
ABOUT YOUR PATROL
DESTINATIONS?
ARE YOU PASSING NEAR
ANY HOSPITAL FACILITIES
SUPERIOR TO OURS?
I'D LIKE VAN GELDER
TO HAVE
THE BEST POSSIBLE
TREATMENT, OF COURSE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I'LL TAKE IT UP
WITH THE SHIP'S SURGEON.
STAND BY.
WELL, BONES,
YOU'VE GOT THE BALL.
YOU CARE TO RECOMMEND
A BETTER PLACE?
THERE ARE
NO SUPERIOR FACILITIES.
HE KNOWS THAT.
BUT THAT'S NOT
THE QUESTION.
IF SOMETHING UNUSUAL
IS GOING ON DOWN THERE...
AN ASSUMPTION,
DOCTOR.
I'M REQUIRED TO ENTER
ANY REASONABLE DOUBTS
INTO MY MEDICAL LOG.
THAT REQUIRES YOU
TO ANSWER IN YOUR LOG.
SORRY, JIM.
DR. ADAMS...
THIS IS
RATHER EMBARRASSING.
BY STRICT INTERPRETATION
OF OUR STARSHIP
REGULATION,
I'M REQUIRED TO INITIATE
AN INVESTIGATION OF THIS
SO THAT A PROPER REPORT--
NO NEED
TO APOLOGIZE,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
IN FACT, I'D TAKE IT
AS A PERSONAL FAVOR
IF YOU'D BEAM DOWN AND
LOOK INTO IT YOURSELF.
I'M SURE YOU REALIZE
WE DON'T GET
TOO MANY VISITORS HERE.
OH, I, UH...
CAPTAIN, I WOULD
APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU COULD COME DOWN
WITH A MINIMUM STAFF.
WE'RE FORCED TO LIMIT
OUTSIDE CONTACT
AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE.
AFFIRMATIVE, DOCTOR.
I'VE VISITED
REHAB COLONIES BEFORE.
ENTERPRISE OUT.
FIND ME SOMEONE
IN YOUR DEPARTMENT
WITH PSYCHIATRIC AND
PENOLOGY EXPERIENCE,
IF POSSIBLE.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2715.2.
STANDARD ORBIT.
PLANET TANTALUS 5.
MISSION--ROUTINE
INVESTIGATION AND REPORT
AS PER SHIP SURGEON'S
MEDICAL LOG.
AS FOR MY LAST ENTRY,
IT SEEMS I WILL GET TO MEET
DR. ADAMS AT LAST.
HOWEVER,
I WOULD HAVE PREFERRED
OTHER CIRCUMSTANCES.
SICK BAY.
REPORT, DOCTOR.
VAN GELDER'S STILL
VIOLENTLY AGITATED,
CAPTAIN.
AND YOU'D PREFER
TO KEEP HIM HERE
UNTIL I COMPLETE
MY INVESTIGATION,
ANYWAY.
I BELIEVE
WE SHOULD, JIM.
OH, I'M ASSIGNING YOU
A TECHNICAL AIDE, CAPTAIN.
ONE OF OUR PSYCHIATRISTS
DOES HAVE A BACKGROUND
IN REHABILITATIVE
THERAPY.
DR. NOEL,
STANDING BY IN
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM NOW.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
BRIDGE OUT.
MR. SPOCK.
COORDINATES.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
READY TO BEAM DOWN.
DR. HELEN NOEL,
CAPTAIN.
WE'VE MET.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER?
THE SCIENCE LAB
CHRISTMAS PARTY?
YES, I REMEMBER.
YOU DROPPED IN--
YES, YES,
I REMEMBER.
PROBLEM, CAPTAIN?
MR. SPOCK,
YOU TELL McCOY THAT
SHE'D BETTER CHECK OUT
AS THE BEST ASSISTANT
I EVER HAD.
ENERGIZE.
IN HERE I PRESUME,
DOCTOR.
PERHAPS
IT WOULD BE SIMPLER
IF YOU CALLED ME
HELEN, CAPTAIN, SINCE--
THIS IS ANOTHER TIME,
ANOTHER PLACE,
AND ANOTHER SITUATION.
WELL, OF COURSE,
CAPTAIN.
ELEVATOR...
AND GOING DOWN
QUITE A WAYS.
I WOULDN'T RECOMMEND IT
FOR WEAK HEARTS.
HELLO, CAPTAIN KIRK...
AND, UH...
DR. HELEN NOEL.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO FINALLY MEET YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
WELCOME TO
DEVIL'S ISLAND, DOCTOR.
PERHAPS YOU'LL
CALL ME HELEN, DOCTOR.
WITH SO
MANY TITLES AROUND,
WE'RE NOT GONNA BE SURE
WHO'S TALKING TO WHO.
I SHALL INDEED.
WON'T YOU?
THANK YOU.
I BELIEVE
REGULATIONS CALL FOR ME
TO CHECK MY WEAPON.
OH, NO,
THAT WON'T BE NECESSARY
IN YOUR CASE, CAPTAIN.
JUST KEEP IT
OUT OF SIGHT.
I KNOW YOU PEOPLE FEEL
AS NAKED WITHOUT A WEAPON
AS WE DO WITHOUT
A MEDIKIT.
[BOTH LAUGH]
A SMALL TOAST.
DO YOU MIND?
IT'S SUCH A GREAT DAY
FOR US HERE ON TANTALUS
WHEN WE HAVE VISITORS,
NO MATTER
WHAT THE EXCUSE.
DOCTOR...
OH, NOW, CAPTAIN,
YOU MADE YOUR APOLOGY
FROM UPSTAIRS.
NOW FORGET IT.
I DON'T THINK
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO GET THROUGH
THE SECURITY SCREEN,
CAPTAIN.
JUST A SECOND.
THERE. NOW TRY IT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE.
YOUR LANDING COORDINATES
WERE RIGHT ON THE NOSE,
MR. SPOCK.
WE ARRIVED SAFELY,
AND WE'RE HERE WITH
DR. ADAMS RIGHT NOW.
KIRK OUT.
AFFIRMATIVE, CAPTAIN.
ENTERPRISE OUT.
AH, LETHE...
COME IN.
LETHE...
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK
AND DR. HELEN NOEL.
LETHE CAME TO US
FOR REHABILITATION
AND STAYED ON
AS A THERAPIST,
AND A VERY GOOD ONE,
TOO, I MIGHT ADD.
I LOVE MY WORK.
GO RIGHT AHEAD,
CAPTAIN.
BEFORE YOU CAME HERE...
I WAS ANOTHER PERSON--
MALIGNANT, HATEFUL.
MAY I ASK WHAT CRIME
YOU COMMITTED?
DOES IT MATTER?
THAT PERSON
NO LONGER EXISTS.
UH, PART OF OUR CURE,
IF YOU WILL, CAPTAIN,
IS TO BURY THE PAST.
WHY SHOULD A PERSON
GO ON LIVING
WITH UNBEARABLE MEMORIES
IF THERE'S NO NECESS--
WELL, I FEEL QUITE SURE
THAT YOU'D CONCUR WITH
ME IN THAT, DOCTOR--
HELEN.
A SHIFTING
OF MEMORY PATTERNS
IS BASIC
TO PSYCHOTHERAPY.
YES. AND NOW
TO THE TOAST, HMM?
YOU'LL FORGIVE US,
LETHE.
THERE YOU ARE,
CAPTAIN.
TO ALL MANKIND...
MAY WE NEVER
FIND SPACE SO VAST,
PLANETS SO COLD,
HEART AND MIND
SO EMPTY
THAT WE CANNOT
FILL THEM
WITH LOVE
AND WARMTH.
QUITE A TOUR, DOCTOR.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
THANK YOU.
HI, CARL.
DOCTOR...
YES?
HMM?
AH...
I WAS AFRAID
YOU WOULD ASK ABOUT
THIS, CAPTAIN.
ONE DOESN'T LIKE
TO TALK ABOUT
THEIR
PERSONAL FAILURES,
YOU KNOW.
IT WAS JUST
AN EXPERIMENT THAT
WENT WRONG, I'M AFRAID.
MAY I SEE IT?
CAPTAIN,
IF SOMETHING
HASN'T WORKED OUT
AND, THEREFORE, HAS
NO SCIENTIFIC FACT--
SHALL WE LEAVE IT
UP TO THE DOCTOR?
SINCE YOU BROUGHT ME
DOWN HERE FOR
ADVICE, CAPTAIN--
ONE OF THE ADVANTAGES
OF BEING A CAPTAIN, DOCTOR,
IS BEING ABLE
TO ASK FOR ADVICE
WITHOUT NECESSARILY
HAVING TO TAKE IT.
I THINK I'LL HAVE
TO AWARD THAT ROUND
TO THE CAPTAIN, HELEN.
YOU'RE FIGHTING
OVER YOUR WEIGHT.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
I'M NOT A CRIMINAL!
I DO NOT REQUIRE...
NEURAL NEUTRALIZER.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN THAT,
DR. VAN GELDER?
A ROOM...
A DEVICE.
DOOR...
CONTROL PANEL.
I SEE IT.
A DEVICE...
A LIGHT!
THE LIGHT!
THIS ROOM...
WHAT HAPPENS THERE?
AAH!
AAH...
A NEURAL
NEUTRALIZER--
EXPERIMENTAL.
ACTUALLY,
WE DON'T EXPECT
TO GET MUCH USE
OUT OF IT AT ALL.
THAT BEAM FROM ABOVE
NEUTRALIZES
BRAIN WAVES.
IT RELAXES
THE PATIENT AS WELL.
IT DOES THEM
NO HARM, OF COURSE,
AND THE EFFECTS
ARE ONLY TEMPORARY.
ONE QUESTION,
DOCTOR.
IF IT DOESN'T
DO ANY GOOD...
WHY DO WE GO ON
USING IT, HMM,
CAPTAIN?
HOPE.
YES. YES,
THERE'S ALWAYS
THAT SLIGHT CHANCE
THAT IT MIGHT DO
SOME GOOD
IN THE MORE
VIOLENT CASES.
TRANQUILIZERS
ARE FINE, CAPTAIN,
BUT TO CONTINUALLY
PUMP CHEMICALS
INTO A PERSON'S BLOOD--
EXACTLY MY POINT,
HELEN. YES.
SHALL WE?
HOW DOES IT WORK?
QUITE SIMPLE.
OFF/ON SWITCHES...
AND THE LARGE CONTROL HERE
CHANGES THE STRENGTH
OF THE BRAIN
NEUTRALIZING BEAM.
CAPTAIN...
YOU REMIND ME
OF THE ANCIENT SKEPTIC
WHO DEMANDED
OF THE WISE OLD SAGE
TO BE TAUGHT
ALL THE WORLD'S WISDOM
WHILE STANDING
ON ONE FOOT.
BEAM NEUTRALIZING
HAS BEEN
EXPERIMENTED WITH
ON EARTH, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT ACQUAINTED
WITH THIS PARTICULAR
STYLE OF EQUIPMENT,
BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT DR. ADAMS
HAS NOT CREATED
A CHAMBER OF
HORRORS HERE.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO
SUGGEST THAT HE HAD.
THE REASON I ASKED, SIR,
WAS YOU HAVEN'T MENTIONED
WHERE DR. VAN GELDER'S
INJURY OCCURRED.
RIGHT HERE, CAPTAIN.
YES.
SIMON WAS
A VERY STUBBORN MAN.
HE COULD HAVE SAT
IN THAT ROOM FOR YEARS
WITH THE BEAM
AT THAT VOLUME,
OR EVEN HIGHER,
OR IF HE SIMPLY HAD
SOMEONE STANDING BY
TO SNAP IT OFF IN CASE
HE GOT INTO TROUBLE, BUT...
NO. HE TRIED IT ALONE
AND ON FULL VOLUME.
IT'S A PITY.
THANK YOU.
YOU WILL FORGET
ALL YOU HAVE HEARD.
TO REMEMBER
ANY PORTION OF IT,
ANY WORD,
WILL CAUSE YOU PAIN,
TERRIBLE PAIN...
GROWING MORE TERRIBLE
AS YOU FIGHT
TO REMEMBER.
CAN YOU GIVE US
YOUR PRESENT LOCATION,
CAPTAIN?
IN DR. ADAMS' STUDY,
MR. SPOCK. WHY?
THEN YOU'RE WITH
DR. ADAMS NOW.
AFFIRMATIVE.
CAPTAIN...
VAN GELDER
HAS MADE REFERENCE
TO A PARTICULAR
TREATMENT ROOM.
THE TERM WAS
NEURAL NEUTRALIZER.
YES. HE WAS INJURED THERE.
I'VE SEEN THE ROOM.
DR. ADAMS
EXPLAINED THE MISTAKE
VAN GELDER MADE.
GO AHEAD, MR. SPOCK.
ANYTHING FURTHER?
YOUR MR. SPOCK SOUNDS
LIKE A VERY EXCELLENT
SECOND IN COMMAND,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
PLEASE TELL HIM TO GO AHEAD
AND SPEAK FREELY.
I HAVE TO CHECK IN WITH
A MEMBER OF MY STAFF ANYWAY.
THANK YOU,
DR. ADAMS.
EXCUSE ME.
STAND BY,
MR. SPOCK.
DR. ADAMS HAS LEFT
WITH SOME THINGS
TO ATTEND TO.
WHAT IS IT,
MR. SPOCK?
VAN GELDER IS EXTREMELY
AGITATED, CAPTAIN,
AND WARNS THAT
YOU ARE IN DANGER.
WELL, THAT'S FOOLISH.
UH, PLEASE REPEAT,
CAPTAIN.
I DIDN'T RECEIVE THAT.
TELL McCOY
THE TECHNICAL EXPERT
HE SENT ALONG WITH ME
INSISTS THAT
ANY CONCERN IS...
UNJUSTIFIED.
ACCORDING TO ADAMS,
VAN GELDER CREATED
HIS OWN PROBLEM.
HE'S SUFFERING FROM
NEURAL SYNAPSE DAMAGE,
AS IF HIS BRAIN
WERE SHORT-CIRCUITED.
IT'S NO WONDER
HE'S HAVING DELUSIONS.
McCOY HERE.
RECEIVED AND UNDERSTOOD.
BUT WE STILL HAVE
SOME DOUBTS UP HERE,
CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU TELL US
ANY MORE?
NOT REALLY.
WHEN DO YOU PLAN
TO BEAM BACK UP, CAPTAIN?
I...
THINK WE'LL SPEND
THE NIGHT HERE,
MR. SPOCK.
NO! NO.
NO. NO.
AND YOU WILL CONTINUE
TO CHECK IN
EVERY 4 HOURS?
AFFIRMATIVE.
KIRK OUT.
NO! NO.
NO, DON'T LET THEM!
YOU MUST WARN
YOUR CAPTAIN.
NO! NO!
DON'T LET HIM STAY!
DON'T! NO. NO.
DON'T HYPO ME.
PLEASE,
I'LL TRY NOT TO FIGHT.
I'LL TRY.
BUT YOU MUST LISTEN.
WARN YOUR CAPTAIN.
DR. ADAMS...
D--
WILL DESTROY...
DESTROY HOW?
WHAT?
RIGHT...
DEATH.
ENTERPRISE LOG.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK,
ACTING CAPTAIN.
I MUST NOW USE
AN ANCIENT VULCAN TECHNIQUE
TO PROBE INTO
VAN GELDER'S TORTURED MIND.
SPOCK, IF THERE'S
THE SLIGHTEST
POSSIBILITY
IT MIGHT HELP--
I'VE NEVER USED IT
ON A HUMAN, DOCTOR.
IF THERE'S ANY WAY
WE CAN LOOK
INTO THIS MAN'S MIND
TO SEE IF
WHAT HE'S SEEING IS
REAL OR DELUSION--
IT'S A HIDDEN,
PERSONAL THING TO
THE VULCAN PEOPLE,
PART OF
OUR PRIVATE LIVES.
NOW, LOOK, SPOCK,
JIM KIRK COULD BE
IN REAL TROUBLE.
WILL IT WORK OR NOT?
IT COULD BE DANGEROUS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT REQUIRES
I MAKE PRESSURE CHANGES...
IN YOUR NERVES,
YOUR BLOOD VESSELS.
YOU MUST...
OPEN MY MIND.
LET ME WARN YOU
AND EXPLAIN TO YOU.
THIS WILL NOT
AFFECT YOU,
DR. McCOY.
ONLY THE PERSON
I TOUCH.
IT IS NOT HYPNOSIS.
I UNDERSTAND.
GOOD.
THE READING'S LEVELING.
YOU BEGIN TO FEEL
A STRANGE EUPHORIA.
YOUR BODY...
FLOATS.
YES.
I BEGIN TO FEEL IT.
OPEN YOUR MIND.
WE MOVE TOGETHER.
OUR MINDS...
SHARING
THE SAME THOUGHTS.
[DOOR BUZZER]
GOOD EVENING.
WHAT DID YOU THINK
OF THE INMATES
WE SAW HERE
THIS AFTERNOON?
YOU COULD'VE WAITED
UNTIL TOMORROW MORNING
TO ASK ME THAT, CAPTAIN.
I DIDN'T.
I THOUGHT
THEY WERE HAPPY,
WELL-ADJUSTED.
BUT A BIT BLANK.
CAPTAIN, IF YOU'RE
QUESTIONING THE METHODS
OF A MAN LIKE
TRISTAN ADAMS--
I'D LIKE TO SEE
THAT TREATMENT ROOM
AGAIN.
YOU SAY YOU'RE
SOMEWHAT FAMILIAR
WITH THE THEORY
BEHIND IT?
YES, SOMEWHAT.
BUT IF YOU'D SIMPLY STATE
ANY DOUBTS YOU HAVE
TO DR. ADAMS--
AND IF HE'S LYING,
HE'LL CONTINUE TO LIE
AND I WON'T FIND OUT
A THING.
THE ONLY WAY
I CAN BE SURE IS TO SEE
THAT MACHINE AT WORK.
OR IS THAT
TOO IMPRACTICAL
AND UNSCIENTIFIC OF ME,
DOCTOR?
WELL?
COMING.
WHAT IS OUR NAME?
WHO ARE WE?
WE ARE SIMON VAN GELDER.
DR. ADAMS...
THE NEURAL NEUTRALIZER.
WHAT DID HE DO TO US?
HE CAN RESHAPE ANY MIND
HE CHOOSES.
HE USED IT
TO ERASE OUR MEMORIES,
PUT HIS OWN THOUGHTS
THERE.
HE WAS SURPRISED
IT TOOK SO MUCH POWER.
WE FOUGHT HIM,
REMEMBER?
BUT WE GREW SO TIRED.
OUR MINDS SO BLANK...
SO OPEN...
THAT ANY THOUGHT
HE PLACED THERE
BECAME OUR THOUGHTS.
OUR MINDS SO EMPTY...
LIKE A SPONGE
NEEDING THOUGHTS,
BEGGING.
EMPTY.
LONELINESS.
SO LONELY TO BE
SITTING THERE EMPTY...
WANTING
ANY WORD FROM HIM.
LOVE.
YES.
HATE.
LIVE.
YES.
DIE.
SUCH AGONY
TO BE EMPTY.
EMPTY.
LONELY.
SO EMPTY.
EMPTY.
I HAVE NO DESIRE
TO DAMAGE MY BRAIN.
CAN THIS BE HANDLED
WITH REASONABLE SAFETY,
YES OR NO?
YES.
AND WILL YOU
BE ABLE TO DETERMINE
IF THAT BEAM IS HARMING ME
IN THE SLIGHTEST?
YES, CAPTAIN.
I KNOW
MY PROFESSION.
READY?
MM-HMM.
WE'LL TRY
MINIMUM INTENSITY--
A SECOND OR TWO.
ANYTIME YOU'RE READY,
DOCTOR.
JUST FOR
A SECOND OR TWO.
WE ALREADY TRIED IT
FOR THAT LONG, CAPTAIN.
NOTHING HAPPENED.
SOMETHING HAPPENED.
YOUR FACE WENT
COMPLETELY BLANK.
TRY A...
HARMLESS SUGGESTION.
YOU'RE HUNGRY.
YOU KNOW,
WHEN WE FINALLY
GET THROUGH THIS,
I'D LIKE TO LOCATE
AND RAID A KITCHEN
SOMEWHERE.
I PUT THAT SUGGESTION
IN YOUR MIND, CAPTAIN.
I SAID SIMPLY
THAT YOU WERE HUNGRY.
REMARKABLY EFFECTIVE
FOR A DEVICE
THAT DR. ADAMS
WAS GOING TO ABANDON.
I THINK WE SHOULD
TRY THIS AGAIN.
YES.
PICK SOMETHING UNUSUAL,
AN UNUSUAL SUGGESTION.
SOMETHING WE CAN
BOTH BE SURE OF.
AT THE CHRISTMAS PARTY...
WE MET.
WE DANCED.
YOU TALKED
ABOUT THE STARS.
I SUGGEST NOW
THAT IT HAPPENED
IN A DIFFERENT WAY.
YOU SWEPT ME
OFF MY FEET
AND CARRIED ME
TO YOUR CABIN.
[LAUGHING]
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
CAPTAIN,
IF YOUR CREW SAW YOU
CARRY ME HERE...
MY CREW...
IS SWORN
TO SECRECY.
BUT MY REPUTATION...
I MEAN,
JUST HAVING
MET LIKE THIS.
OF COURSE,
IT WOULD BE DIFFERENT
IF YOU CARED FOR ME.
YOU WANT ME
TO MANUFACTURE A LIE,
WRAP IT UP AS A...
CHRISTMAS PRESENT
FOR YOU?
NO.
I'D PREFER HONESTY.
NOW CAPTAIN KIRK
IS GOING TO HAVE
A COMPLETE
DEMONSTRATION.
I WANT THERE TO BE
NO DOUBTS WHATSOEVER
IN HIS MIND.
[GROANS]
YOU'RE MADLY IN LOVE
WITH HELEN, CAPTAIN.
YOU'D LIE, CHEAT,
STEAL FOR HER,
SACRIFICE YOUR CAREER,
YOUR REPUTATION.
NO, DOCTOR, NO!
THE PAIN,
DO YOU FEEL IT,
CAPTAIN?
YOU MUST HAVE HER,
OR THE PAIN GROWS WORSE.
THE PAIN,
THE LONGING FOR HER.
HELEN.
FOR YEARS
YOU'VE LOVED HER, CAPTAIN.
FOR YEARS.
FOR YEARS
I'VE LOVED YOU.
YOU MUST CONTINUE
TO REMEMBER THAT, CAPTAIN.
AND NOW...SHE'S GONE.
HELEN.
HELEN, DON'T GO.
I NEED YOU, HELEN!
NOW, CAPTAIN...
YOU MUST TAKE
YOUR PHASER WEAPON
AND DROP IT
ON THE FLOOR.
CAPTAIN?
THE PAIN INCREASES
UNLESS YOU OBEY ME.
I...
MUST...
DROP IT.
VERY GOOD, CAPTAIN.
VERY GOOD INDEED.
AND NOW
YOUR COMMUNICATOR--
DROP IT ON THE FLOOR.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
AAH!
KIRK...
TO ENTERPRISE.
AAH!
NO!
[SOBBING]
THEY'VE TAKEN YOU
FROM THE ROOM, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE IN
YOUR OWN QUARTERS NOW.
HELEN...
FOR YEARS,
I'VE LOVED YOU.
HELEN...
TRY TO REMEMBER.
I'VE LOVED YOU...
HE PLACED ALL THAT
IN YOUR MIND.
FOR YEARS.
REMEMBER.
DR. ADAMS
TOOK THE CONTROLS
AWAY FROM ME.
DO YOU REMEMBER
THE PAIN,
AND THEN HIS VOICE?
REMEMBER?
YES.
I...
REMEMBER.
HELEN...
LOOK.
THE DUCT.
UHH.
GIVE ME A HAND HERE.
PULL.
AIR CONDITIONING.
IT HAS TO CONNECT
WITH OTHER DUCTS
AND TUNNELS.
YOU CAN
GET THROUGH THIS.
IT MIGHT LEAD
TO THE POWER SUPPLY.
SHORT-CIRCUITED,
IT WOULD CUT OFF
THE SECURITY
FORCE FIELD.
HAVE YOU HAD
ANY TRAINING
IN HYPER-POWER
CIRCUITS?
NO.
MEGAVOLTAGE.
TOUCH THE WRONG LINE
AND YOU'RE DEAD.
ANYTHING'S BETTER THAN
ADAMS' TREATMENT ROOM.
TIME FOR ANOTHER
TREATMENT?
PLEASE DON'T FIGHT ME,
CAPTAIN.
THE PAIN
ONLY GETS WORSE
WHEN YOU DOUBT ME.
UHH.
UHH!
[SCREAMS]
YOU BELIEVE IN ME
COMPLETELY.
I BELIEVE IN YOU.
YOU TRUST ME
COMPLETELY.
I...
TRUST YOU.
EXCELLENT, CAPTAIN.
I COMPLIMENT YOU.
DO YOU KNOW
DR. VAN GELDER
WAS DOWN
ON HIS HANDS AND KNEES
SOBBING AT THIS POINT?
IT WAS SO GRATIFYING.
I'M SO FORTUNATE
TO HAVE HAD A COUPLE
OF EXCELLENT SPECIMENS
TO--TO WORK WITH.
I'VE LEARNED
A GREAT DEAL.
THE WOMAN DOCTOR--
SHE'S GONE,
DR. ADAMS.
NOTIFY SECURITY
AT ONCE, LETHE.
WHERE IS SHE,
CAPTAIN?
I...
AAH!
DON'T KNOW.
WHERE IS HELEN?
AND WITH WHAT
INSTRUCTIONS?
UHH.
I...
DON'T...
KNOW.
EMERGENCY CHANNEL D.
IT'S NO GOOD,
MR. SPOCK.
I CAN'T BREAK THROUGH
THEIR FORCE FIELD.
KEEP TRYING.
PUT HIM BACK
IN THE CHAIR, ELI.
AND FIND THAT GIRL.
AAH!
UHH!
MR. SPOCK,
THE FORCE FIELD IS GONE.
I CAN SEND YOU
RIGHT TO THE SOURCE
OF THE INTERRUPTION.
GET SOME SECURITY PEOPLE
AND FOLLOW ME DOWN.
ENERGIZE.
[COMMUNICATOR CHIRPS]
ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS SPOCK.
THE FORCE FIELD
HAS BEEN ELIMINATED.
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN?
HELEN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
OH, THIS ISN'T RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
DR. ADAMS
DID THIS TO YOU.
DR. ADAMS?
DR. AD--
THE TREATMENT ROOM.
FOLLOW ME.
McCoy: JIM!
THE POWER CAME ON.
HE'S DEAD, CAPTAIN.
THE MACHINE WASN'T
ON HIGH ENOUGH TO KILL HIM.
BUT HE WAS ALONE.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
A MIND...
EMPTIED
BY THAT THING?
WITHOUT EVEN
A TORMENTER
FOR COMPANY.
I UNDERSTAND.
Man: ALL SECTIONS.
SECURITY CHECK
IN PROGRESS. REPORT.
OH, CAPTAIN,
THERE WAS A MESSAGE
FROM TANTALUS COLONY, SIR.
IT WAS FROM
VAN GELDER.
HE THOUGHT
YOU'D LIKE TO KNOW
THE TREATMENT ROOM
HAD BEEN DISMANTLED,
THE EQUIPMENT DESTROYED.
THANK YOU.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
THAT A MAN COULD DIE
OF LONELINESS.
NOT WHEN YOU'VE
SAT IN THAT ROOM.
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT,
MR. SPOCK.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR ONE.
ACKNOWLEDGED, CAPTAIN.
WARP FACTOR ONE.