ONE DEGREE
TO OVERLAP.
STAND BY TO PHOTOGRAPH.
NOW.
[SIGHS]
THREE DAYS
OF THIS NOW, SIR.
OTHER SHIPS MUST HAVE
MADE STAR MAPS
OF SOME OF THIS.
NEGATIVE,
LIEUTENANT.
WE ARE THE FIRST
TO REACH THIS FAR.
[BEEPING]
SIR, CONTACT
WITH AN OBJECT.
IT'S MOVING
TOWARD US.
NO VISUAL
CONTACT YET.
DEFLECTORS,
FULL INTENSITY.
IT'S COMING
AT LIGHT SPEED.
COLLISION COURSE.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS,
MR. SULU.
OBJECT CHANGING DIRECTION,
TOO, SIR.
KEEPS COMING AT US.
I'M GETTING NO SIGNAL
FROM IT, SIR.
STILL COLLISION COURSE.
DEFLECTORS AREN'T
STOPPING IT.
SOUND ALARM.
IT'S SLOWING DOWN,
MR. SPOCK.
COUNTERMAND ALARM.
ALL ENGINES FULL STOP.
VISUAL CONTACT.
AHEAD SLOW.
STEER A COURSE
AROUND IT, MR. SULU.
IT'S BLOCKING THE WAY!
QUITE UNNECESSARY TO RAISE
YOUR VOICE, MR. BAILEY.
ALL ENGINES STOP.
SOUND THE ALERT.
BRIDGE TO ALL DECKS--
CONDITION ALERT.
ALL DECKS--
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THE BRIDGE.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 1512.2.
ON OUR THIRD DAY
OF STAR MAPPING,
AN UNEXPLAINED
CUBICAL OBJECT
BLOCKED OUR VESSEL'S PATH.
ON THE BRIDGE,
MR. SPOCK IMMEDIATELY
ORDERED GENERAL ALERT.
MY LOCATION--SICK BAY.
QUARTERLY PHYSICAL CHECK.
OH! WHEW!
JUST A FEW SECONDS MORE.
[MUTTERING]
[GROANING]
THAT'S A BOY.
KEEP IT UP.
WORK OFF A LITTLE SWEAT,
DO YOU GOOD.
KILLIN' ME.
[GROANING]
OHH! YOU'RE KILLING ME.
STOP.
OH! AH.
WINDED?
YOU'D BE THE LAST
ONE I'D TELL.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HAVE A LOOK AT THIS,
CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S THAT?
UNDETERMINED.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT'S BLOCKING OUR WAY.
WHEN WE MOVE,
IT MOVES AS WELL.
A VESSEL OF SOME KIND?
NEGATIVE.
MORE SOME TYPE OF DEVICE.
I'LL BE RIGHT UP.
YOU COULD SEE
THE ALARM LIGHTS
FLASHING FROM THERE,
McCOY.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL ME?
FINALLY FINISHED
A PHYSICAL ON YOU,
DIDN'T I?
WHAT AM I, A DOCTOR
OR A MOON SHUTTLE CONDUCTOR?
IF I JUMPED EVERY TIME
A LIGHT CAME ON
AROUND HERE,
I'D END UP
TALKING TO MYSELF.
Man on P.A.:
ALL DECKS ALERT.
[SIREN]
BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN TO BRIDGE.
Spock: SPOCK HERE.
ANY CHANGES?
NEGATIVE.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT SEEMS TO WANT
TO JUST HOLD US HERE.
ANY INDICATION OF DANGER
FROM IT?
NEGATIVE.
I'LL CHANGE FIRST, THEN.
CAPTAIN OUT.
ALL DECKS HAVE
REPORTED GREEN,
MR. BAILEY.
YES, SIR.
AND WHEN THE CAPTAIN
ARRIVES, HE'LL EXPECT
A FULL REPORT ON--
THE CUBE'S RANGE
AND POSITION.
I'LL HAVE IT BY THEN.
RAISING MY VOICE
BACK THERE
DOESN'T MEAN I WAS SCARED
OR COULDN'T DO MY JOB.
IT MEANS I HAPPEN
TO HAVE A HUMAN THING
CALLED AN ADRENALINE GLAND.
HMM. IT DOES SOUND MOST
INCONVENIENT, HOWEVER.
HAVE YOU CONSIDERED
HAVING IT REMOVED?
VERY FUNNY.
YOU TRY TO CROSS
BRAINS WITH SPOCK,
HE'LL CUT YOU TO
PIECES EVERY TIME.
CAPTAIN TO BRIDGE.
SPOCK HERE.
ANY SIGNS OF LIFE?
NEGATIVE.
HAVE YOU TRIED ALL
HAILING FREQUENCIES?
AFFIRMATIVE. NO ANSWER
FROM THE CUBE.
HAVE THE DEPARTMENT HEADS
MEET ME ON THE BRIDGE.
ALREADY STANDING BY.
[BEEPING]
REPORTING, SIR.
SENSORS SHOW
IT IS SOLID,
BUT ITS COMPOSITION
IS UNKNOWN TO US.
LIEUTENANT UHURA?
HAILING FREQUENCIES
STILL OPEN, SIR.
I GET NO MESSAGE
FROM IT.
NAVIGATION.
DISTANCE FROM US--
1,593 METERS,
POSITION CONSTANT.
EACH OF ITS EDGES
MEASURES 107 METERS.
MASS, A LITTLE UNDER
11,000 METRIC TONS.
SCOTTY.
MODE OF POWER?
BEATS ME WHAT
MAKES IT GO.
I'LL BUY
SPECULATION.
I'D SELL IT
IF I HAD ANY.
THAT'S A SOLID CUBE.
HOW SOMETHING LIKE THAT
CAN SENSE US COMING,
BLOCK US,
MOVE WHEN WE MOVE,
IT BEATS ME.
THAT'S MY REPORT.
LIFE SCIENCES.
SAME REPORT.
SIR, WE GOING TO JUST
LET IT HOLD US HERE?
WE'VE GOT PHASER WEAPONS.
I VOTE WE BLAST IT.
I'LL KEEP THAT IN MIND,
MR. BAILEY,
WHEN THIS BECOMES
A DEMOCRACY.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 1513.8.
STAR MAPS REVEAL
NO INDICATION
OF HABITABLE
PLANETS NEARBY.
ORIGIN AND PURPOSE
OF THE CUBE
STILL UNKNOWN.
WE'VE BEEN HERE,
HELD MOTIONLESS,
FOR 18 HOURS.
ANYTHING FURTHER,
GENTLEMEN?
I BELIEVE IT ADDS UP
TO EITHER ONE OF
TWO POSSIBILITIES.
FIRST, A SPACE BUOY
OF SOME KIND.
SECOND?
FLYPAPER.
AND YOU DON'T RECOMMEND
STICKING AROUND.
NEGATIVE.
IT WOULD MAKE US
APPEAR TOO WEAK.
IT'S TIME FOR ACTION,
GENTLEMEN.
MR. BAILEY--
BRIDGE TO PHASER
GUN CREW--
COUNTERMAND.
I'LL SELECT
WHAT KIND OF ACTION,
MR. BAILEY--
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I THOUGHT--
ARE YOU EXPLAINING,
MR. BAILEY?
I HAVEN'T REQUESTED
AN EXPLANATION.
NOW, AS I WAS ABOUT
TO SAY, NAVIGATOR,
PLOT US A SPIRAL COURSE
AWAY FROM THE CUBE.
YES, SIR.
WE'LL TRY PULLING
AWAY FROM IT.
YES, SIR.
HELMSMAN
TO ENGINE ROOM,
STAND BY.
ALL DECKS ALERT.
WE'RE GOING TO
TRY PULLING AWAY.
COURSE PLOTTED
AND LAID IN, SIR.
ENGAGE, MR. SULU,
QUARTER SPEED.
.25, SIR.
STILL BLOCKING US, SIR.
LET'S SEE IF IT'LL GIVE WAY.
AHEAD, HALF SPEED.
.50, SIR.
RADIATION FROM THE SHORT
END OF THE SPECTRUM INCREASING.
ALL STOP, FULL POSITION.
IT'S STILL
COMING TOWARD US.
RANGE 190 METERS.
RADIATION INCREASING.
POWER ASTERN,
HALF SPEED.
RADIATION NEARING
THE TOLERANCE LEVEL.
STILL COMING.
GAINING ON US.
ENGINES ASTERN,
FULL SPEED.
RANGE--125 METERS NOW.
HELM, GIVE US WARP SPEED.
WARP ONE, SIR.
RADIATION AT
THE TOLERANCE LEVEL.
WARP TWO, SIR.
SPEED IS NOW
WARP THREE.
RADIATION PASSING
THE TOLERANCE LEVEL,
ENTERING LETHAL ZONE.
RANGE--51 METERS
AND STILL CLOSING, SIR.
PHASER CREW STAND READY.
PHASER CREW
REPORTS READY, SIR.
GROWING. WE CAN TAKE
ONLY A FEW MORE
SECONDS OF THIS.
LOCK PHASERS ON TARGET.
MR. BAILEY, LOCK PHASERS!
PHASERS LOCKED
ON TARGET, SIR.
AT POINT-BLANK RANGE
AND CLOSING.
FIRE MAIN PHASERS.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 1514.0.
THE CUBE HAS BEEN
DESTROYED.
SHIP'S DAMAGE--MINOR.
BUT MY NEXT
DECISION--MAJOR.
PROBE ON AHEAD
OR TURN BACK.
NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
NO CONTACTS, NO OBJECTS
IN ANY DIRECTION.
CARE TO SPECULATE
ON WHAT WE'LL FIND
IF WE GO ON AHEAD?
SPECULATE?
NO.
LOGICALLY, WE'LL DISCOVER
THE INTELLIGENCE
WHICH SENT OUT THE CUBE.
INTELLIGENCE
DIFFERENT FROM OURS
OR SUPERIOR?
PROBABLY BOTH.
AND IF YOU'RE ASKING
THE LOGICAL DECISION
TO MAKE--
NO, I'M NOT.
THE MISSION OF
THE ENTERPRISE
IS TO SEEK OUT
AND CONTACT ALIEN LIFE.
HAS IT OCCURRED TO YOU
THAT THERE'S
A CERTAIN...INEFFICIENCY
IN CONSTANTLY
QUESTIONING ME ON THINGS
YOU'VE ALREADY MADE UP
YOUR MIND ABOUT?
IT GIVES ME
EMOTIONAL SECURITY.
NAVIGATOR,
SET A COURSE AHEAD.
PLOTTED.
LAID IN, SIR.
ENGAGE.
WARP ONE, SIR.
MR. BAILEY--
PHASER CREWS
WERE SLUGGISH.
YOU WERE SLOW
IN LOCKING THEM
INTO YOUR
DIRECTIONAL BEAM.
HELMSMAN,
ENGINEERING DECKS
COULD HAVE BEEN FASTER, TOO.
PROGRAM A SERIES
OF SIMULATED ATTACKS
AND EVASION MANEUVERS.
KEEP REPEATING
THE EXERCISE
UNTIL WE'RE PROFICIENT,
GENTLEMEN.
YES, SIR.
YOUR TIMING
IS LOUSY, JIM.
YOUR MEN ARE TIRED.
CAPTAIN'S QUARTERS.
AREN'T YOU THE ONE
THAT ALWAYS SAYS
A LITTLE SUFFERING
IS GOOD FOR THE SOUL?
I NEVER SAY THAT.
THIS IS THE BRIDGE.
PREPARE FOR
SIMULATED ATTACK.
I'M ESPECIALLY
WORRIED ABOUT BAILEY.
NAVIGATOR'S POSITION'S
ROUGH ENOUGH FOR
A SEASONED MAN.
I THINK
HE'LL CUT IT.
OH? HOW SO SURE?
BECAUSE YOU SPOTTED
SOMETHING YOU LIKED IN HIM,
SOMETHING FAMILIAR,
LIKE YOURSELF, SAY ABOUT,
OH, 11 YEARS AGO?
ON THE DOUBLE,
DECK FIVE!
GIVE ME A GREEN LIGHT.
WHY, DOCTOR,
YOU'VE BEEN READING
YOUR TEXTBOOKS AGAIN?
I DON'T
NEED TEXTBOOKS
TO KNOW THAT YOU COULD'VE
PROMOTED HIM TOO FAST.
LISTEN TO THAT VOICE.
CONDITION ALERT.
BATTLE STATIONS.
ENGINEERING,
DECK FIVE, REPORT.
PHASER CREWS, COME ON,
LET'S GET WITH IT.
PHASER STATION TWO,
WHERE'S YOUR GREEN LIGHT?
WHAT'S NEXT?
"THEY'RE NOT
MACHINES, JIM"?
WELL, THEY'RE NOT.
AFTER WHAT
THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH--
DR. McCOY,
I'VE HEARD YOU SAY
THAT MAN
IS ULTIMATELY SUPERIOR
TO ANY
MECHANICAL DEVICE.
NO, I NEVER
SAY THAT, EITHER.
I COULD'VE SWORN
I HEARD YOU SAY THAT.
[COMMUNICATOR SIGNAL]
KIRK HERE.
Spock:
EXERCISE RATING,
CAPTAIN--94%.
LET'S TRY FOR 100,
MR. SPOCK.
AGREED.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO WITH THAT 6%
WHEN THEY GIVE IT TO YOU, JIM?
I'M GOING TO TAKE IT,
AND I'M GOING TO--
[DOOR OPENS]
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
IT'S PAST TIME
YOU HAD SOMETHING
TO EAT, SIR.
WHAT THE DEVIL IS THIS?
GREEN LEAVES?
IT'S DIETARY SALAD,
SIR.
DR. McCOY ORDERED
YOUR DIET CARD
CHANGED.
I THOUGHT YOU KNEW.
YOUR WEIGHT WAS UP
A COUPLE OF POUNDS.
REMEMBER?
WILL YOU STOP HOVERING
OVER ME, YEOMAN?
WELL, I'LL CHANGE IT
IF YOU DON'T
LIKE IT, SIR.
BRING SOME
FOR THE DOCTOR, TOO.
NO, NO. NO, I NEVER EAT
UNTIL THE CREW EATS.
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
YOU'RE WELCOME, SIR.
[BAILEY]
THIS IS THE BRIDGE.
ALL DECKS PREPARE
TO BETTER REACTION TIME
ON SECOND
SIMULATED ATTACK.
WHEN I GET MY HANDS
ON THE HEADQUARTERS
GENIUS
THAT ASSIGNED ME
A FEMALE YEOMAN--
WHAT'S THE MATTER, JIM,
DON'T YOU TRUST YOURSELF?
BATTLE STATIONS.
ENGINEERING DECKS ALERT...
I'VE ALREADY
GOT A FEMALE
TO WORRY ABOUT.
HER NAME'S
THE ENTERPRISE.
ENGINEERING
DECKS ALERT.
PHASER CREWS, LET'S--
Sulu:
COUNTERMAND THAT.
ALL DECKS
TO BATTLE STATIONS.
THIS IS NOT
A DRILL.
REPEAT--THIS IS
NOT A DRILL.
KIRK HERE.
Spock:
WE'RE PICKING UP
AN OBJECT, SIR.
MUCH LARGER,
COMING TOWARD US.
COMING.
EXCEPTIONALLY
STRONG CONTACT.
NOT VISUAL YET.
DISTANT SPECTROGRAPH.
METALLIC,
SIMILAR TO CUBE.
MUCH GREATER
ENERGY READING.
THERE, SIR.
HALF SPEED.
PREPARE FOR
EVASIVE ACTION.
REDUCING TO
WARP TWO, SIR.
TRACTOR BEAM, CAPTAIN.
SOMETHING'S
GRABBED US--HARD.
ENGINES
OVERLOADING, SIR.
ALL ENGINES STOP.
ALL ENGINES
STOPPED, SIR.
PHASER CREWS STAND READY.
BRIDGE TO PHASER
CREWS, STAND READY.
FORWARD PHASER,
WILL COMPLY.
ALL WEAPONS AT
OPERATIONAL READY.
FASCINATING.
WHAT'S ITS MASS,
MR. SPOCK?
READING GOES OFF
MY SCALE, CAPTAIN.
MUST BE A MILE
IN DIAMETER.
5,000 METERS AWAY
AND IT STILL
FILLS THE SCREEN.
REDUCE IMAGE.
LET ME SEE ALL OF IT.
MAGNIFICATION
2.5, SIR.
18.5, SIR.
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE UNITED
EARTH SHIP ENTERPRISE.
WE CONVEY GREETINGS
AND AWAIT YOUR REPLY.
WHAT IS IT, MR. BAILEY?
A MESSAGE...
COMING OVER
MY NAVIGATION BEAM.
PICK IT UP.
SWITCHING, SIR.
...AND TRESPASSED
INTO OUR STAR SYSTEMS.
THIS IS BALOK,
COMMANDER OF
THE FLAGSHIP FESARIUS
OF THE FIRST FEDERATION.
YOUR VESSEL,
OBVIOUSLY THE PRODUCT
OF A PRIMITIVE
AND SAVAGE CIVILIZATION,
HAVING IGNORED
A WARNING BUOY
AND HAVING THEN
DESTROYED IT,
HAS DEMONSTRATED YOUR
INTENTION IS NOT PEACEFUL.
WE ARE NOW CONSIDERING THE
DISPOSITION OF YOUR SHIP
AND THE LIFE ABOARD.
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE ENTERPRISE SPEAKING.
THE WARNING NATURE
OF YOUR SPACE BUOY
WAS UNKNOWN TO US.
OUR VESSEL WAS BLOCKED,
AND WHEN WE ATTEMPTED
TO DISENGAGE--
[STATIC]
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE BEING INVADED
BY EXCEPTIONALLY
STRONG SENSOR PROBES,
EVERYWHERE--
OUR ELECTRICAL SYSTEMS,
OUR ENGINES--
NO FURTHER COMMUNICATION
WILL BE ACCEPTED.
IF THERE IS THE SLIGHTEST
HOSTILE MOVE,
YOUR VESSEL WILL BE
DESTROYED IMMEDIATELY.
THEY'RE SHUTTING OFF
SOME OF OUR SYSTEMS, CAPTAIN.
BRILLIANT.
EXTREMELY SOPHISTICATED
IN THEIR METHODS.
DOES THE RECORDER
MARKER HAVE THIS
ON ITS TAPES?
ENOUGH TO WARN
OTHER EARTH SHIPS.
MR. BAILEY, DISPATCH
RECORDER MARKER.
MR. BAILEY.
UH, RECORDER MARKER
DISPATCHED, SIR.
MARKER ON COURSE.
HEADING BACK
THE WAY WE--
YOUR RECORDER MARKER
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
YOU HAVE BEEN EXAMINED.
YOUR SHIP
MUST BE DESTROYED.
WE MAKE ASSUMPTION
YOU HAVE A DEITY OR DEITIES
OR SOME SUCH BELIEFS
WHICH COMFORT YOU.
WE THEREFORE GRANT YOU
10 EARTH TIME PERIODS
KNOWN AS MINUTES
TO MAKE PREPARATIONS.
MIGHT BE INTERESTING
TO SEE WHAT THEY LOOK LIKE
IF I CAN LOCATE
WHERE THAT VOICE
IS COMING FROM.
BALOK'S MESSAGE--
IT WAS HEARD
ALL OVER THE SHIP.
CAPTAIN TO CREW--
THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE
SERVED FOR LONG
ON THIS VESSEL
HAVE ENCOUNTERED
ALIEN LIFE FORMS.
YOU KNOW THE GREATEST DANGER
FACING US IS OURSELVES
AND IRRATIONAL FEAR
OF THE UNKNOWN,
BUT THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS THE UNKNOWN.
ONLY THINGS TEMPORARILY HIDDEN,
TEMPORARILY NOT UNDERSTOOD.
IN MOST CASES,
WE HAVE FOUND
THAT INTELLIGENCE
CAPABLE OF A CIVILIZATION
IS CAPABLE OF UNDERSTANDING
PEACEFUL GESTURES.
SURELY A LIFE FORM
ADVANCED ENOUGH
FOR SPACE TRAVEL
IS ADVANCED ENOUGH
TO EVENTUALLY UNDERSTAND
OUR MOTIVES.
ALL DECKS, STAND BY.
CAPTAIN OUT.
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
WE CAME SEEKING
FRIENDSHIP.
BUT WE HAVE NO WISH
TO TRESPASS.
TO DEMONSTRATE
OUR GOOD WILL,
OUR VESSEL WILL NOW
RETURN THE WAY IT CAME.
WE--
[LOW HUMMING]
LAY IN A COURSE AHEAD,
MR. BAILEY.
WHAT? A COURSE?
PLOTTED AND
LAID IN, SIR.
ENGAGE, WARP FACTOR ONE.
WARP FACTOR--
THERE'S
NO RESPONSE.
SWITCH TO IMPULSE.
ALL ENGINE
SYSTEMS
SHOW DEAD.
AND WEAPON
SYSTEMS.
SWITCHING TO SCREEN.
I BELIEVE I CAN
GET SOMETHING VISUAL.
YOU ARE WASTING TIME
AND EFFORT.
THERE IS NO ESCAPE.
YOU HAVE
EIGHT EARTH MINUTES LEFT.
I WAS CURIOUS TO SEE
HOW THEY APPEARED.
YES, OF COURSE YOU WERE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THIS.
SPOCK'S WASTING TIME.
EVERYBODY ELSE
JUST SITTING AROUND.
SOMEBODY'S GOT
TO DO SOMETHING.
EASY, BAILEY.
WHAT DO THEY
WANT FROM US?
LET'S FIND OUT
WHAT THEY WANT US
TO DO!
THEY WANT US
TO LOSE OUR HEADS.
WE'VE ONLY GOT
EIGHT MINUTES LEFT.
7 MINUTES
AND 45 SECONDS.
HE'S DOING
A COUNTDOWN!
PRACTICALLY
END OF WATCH.
ARE YOU ALL
OUT OF YOUR MINDS?
END OF WATCH?
IT'S THE END
OF EVERYTHING.
WHAT ARE YOU, ROBOTS?
WOUND-UP TOY SOLDIERS?
DON'T YOU KNOW
WHEN YOU'RE DYING?
WATCH AND REGULATIONS
AND ORDERS--
WHAT DO THEY MEAN?
BAILEY, YOU'RE RELIEVED!
ESCORT HIM
TO HIS QUARTERS, DOCTOR.
LET'S GO.
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE ENTERPRISE SPEAKING.
IT IS THE CUSTOM
OF EARTH PEOPLE
TO TRY AND AVOID
MISUNDERSTANDING
WHENEVER POSSIBLE.
WE DESTROYED
YOUR SPACE BUOY
AS A SIMPLE ACT
OF SELF-PRESERVATION.
WHEN WE ATTEMPTED
TO MOVE AWAY FROM IT,
IT EMITTED RADIATION
HARMFUL TO OUR SPECIES.
IF YOU'VE EXAMINED
OUR SHIP AND ITS TAPES,
YOU KNOW THIS TO BE TRUE.
[ELECTRONIC HUMMING]
YOU NOW HAVE
SEVEN MINUTES LEFT.
4 MINUTES,
30 SECONDS.
YOU HAVE
AN ANNOYING FASCINATION
FOR TIMEPIECES,
MR. SULU.
JIM...
4 MINUTES.
WHAT'S A MATTER
WITH THEM OUT THERE?
THEY MUST KNOW
WE MEAN THEM NO HARM.
THEY'RE CERTAINLY
AWARE BY NOW
THAT WE'RE TOTALLY
INCAPABLE OF IT.
THERE MUST BE
SOMETHING TO DO,
SOMETHING
I'VE OVERLOOKED.
IN CHESS,
WHEN ONE IS OUTMATCHED,
THE GAME IS OVER.
CHECKMATE.
IS THAT YOUR
BEST RECOMMENDATION?
I'M SOR--
I REGRET THAT I
CAN FIND NO OTHER
LOGICAL ALTERNATIVE.
ASSUMING WE GET OUT
OF THIS, CAPTAIN--
NOBODY'S GIVEN UP YET.
WELL, THEN ABOUT BAILEY.
LET ME ENTER IT
IN MY MEDICAL RECORDS
AS SIMPLE FATIGUE.
THAT'S MY DECISION,
DOCTOR.
AND YOUR MISTAKE.
YOU OVERWORKED HIM,
PUSHED HIM,
EXPECTED TOO MUCH
OUT OF HIM--
I'M ORDERING YOU
TO DROP IT.
I HAVE NO TIME FOR YOU,
YOUR THEORIES,
YOUR QUAINT
PHILOSOPHIES...
I INTEND TO CHALLENGE
YOUR ACTIONS IN
MY MEDICAL RECORDS.
I'LL STATE THAT I WARNED YOU
ABOUT BAILEY'S CONDITION.
NOW THAT'S NO BLUFF.
ANY TIME YOU CAN
BLUFF ME, DOCTOR--
THREE MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR.
LET'S HOPE WE HAVE TIME
TO ARGUE ABOUT IT.
NOT CHESS, MR. SPOCK.
POKER.
DO YOU KNOW THE GAME?
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
OUR RESPECT
FOR OTHER LIFE FORMS
REQUIRES THAT WE
GIVE YOU THIS WARNING.
ONE CRITICAL ITEM
OF INFORMATION
THAT HAS NEVER BEEN
INCORPORATED
INTO THE MEMORY BANKS
OF ANY EARTH SHIP.
SINCE THE EARLY YEARS
OF SPACE EXPLORATION,
EARTH VESSELS HAVE HAD
INCORPORATED INTO THEM
A SUBSTANCE KNOWN AS...
CORBOMITE.
IT IS A MATERIAL
AND A DEVICE
WHICH PREVENTS ATTACK ON US.
IF ANY DESTRUCTIVE ENERGY
TOUCHES OUR VESSEL,
A REVERSE REACTION
OF EQUAL STRENGTH
IS CREATED,
DESTROYING--
YOU NOW HAVE TWO MINUTES.
DESTROYING
THE ATTACKER!
IT MAY INTEREST YOU
TO KNOW
THAT SINCE THE INITIAL USE
OF CORBOMITE
MORE THAN TWO
OF OUR CENTURIES AGO,
NO ATTACKING VESSEL
HAS SURVIVED THE ATTEMPT.
DEATH HAS
LITTLE MEANING TO US.
IF IT HAS NONE TO YOU...
THEN ATTACK US NOW.
WE GROW ANNOYED
AT YOUR FOOLISHNESS.
HOWEVER,
IT WAS WELL PLAYED.
I REGRET NOT HAVING LEARNED
MORE ABOUT THIS BALOK.
IN SOME MANNER,
HE WAS REMINISCENT
OF MY FATHER.
THEN MAY HEAVEN HAVE
HELPED YOUR MOTHER.
QUITE THE CONTRARY.
SHE CONSIDERED HERSELF
A VERY FORTUNATE
EARTH WOMAN.
DOC...
SORRY.
FOR HAVING OTHER THINGS
ON YOUR MIND? MY FAULT.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW ON EARTH
YOU EVER KEPT
FROM PUNCHING ME
IN THE FACE.
ONE MINUTE.
I KNEW HE WOULD.
IF ANYONE'S
INTERESTED...
30 SECONDS.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO RETURN TO POST, SIR.
PERMISSION GRANTED.
11...
10 SECONDS.
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1.
A VERY
INTERESTING GAME,
THIS POKER.
IT DOES HAVE ADVANTAGES
OVER CHESS.
LOVE TO TEACH IT TO YOU.
THIS IS THE COMMANDER
OF THE FESARIUS.
HERE IT COMES.
IS IT RAISE OR CALL?
THE DESTRUCTION
OF YOUR VESSEL
HAS BEEN DELAYED.
WE WILL RELENT
IN YOUR DESTRUCTION
ONLY IF WE HAVE PROOF
OF YOUR CORBOMITE DEVICE.
HOLD ON THAT.
LET HIM SWEAT
FOR A CHANGE.
SHIP TO SHIP.
HAILING FREQUENCIES, SIR.
REQUEST DENIED.
I HAVE VISUAL CONTACT,
CAPTAIN.
WE WILL SOON INFORM YOU
OF OUR DECISION
REGARDING YOUR VESSEL.
AND HAVING PERMITTED
YOUR PRIMITIVE EFFORTS
TO SEE MY FORM,
I TRUST IT HAS PLEASED
YOUR CURIOSITY.
AND NOW,
ANOTHER DEMONSTRATION
OF OUR SUPERIORITY.
I THOUGHT THE POWER
WAS OFF IN THE GALLEY.
I USED A HAND PHASER,
AND ZAP--HOT COFFEE.
SOMETHING'S GOING ON,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S A SMALL SHIP.
ABOUT 2,000 METRIC TONS.
IT HAS BEEN DECIDED
THAT I WILL CONDUCT YOU
TO A PLANET
OF THE FIRST FEDERATION
WHICH IS CAPABLE
OF SUSTAINING
YOUR LIFE FORM.
THERE YOU WILL DISEMBARK
AND BE INTERNED.
YOUR SHIP WILL BE
DESTROYED, OF COURSE.
ENGINE SYSTEMS
COMING ON, CAPTAIN.
DO NOT BE DECEIVED
BY THE SIZE
OF THIS PILOT VESSEL.
IT HAS AN EQUAL POTENTIAL
TO DESTROY YOUR VESSEL.
TRACTOR BEAM AGAIN.
SO THAT YOU MAY SUSTAIN
YOUR GRAVITY
AND ATMOSPHERE,
YOUR SYSTEMS
ARE NOW OPEN.
ESCAPE IS IMPOSSIBLE
SINCE YOU ARE BEING TAKEN
UNDER OUR POWER
TO YOUR DESTINATION.
ANY MOVE TO ESCAPE
OR DESTROY THIS SHIP
WILL RESULT IN
THE INSTANT DESTRUCTION
OF THE ENTERPRISE
AND EVERYONE ABOARD.
WE'RE BEING TOWED, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 1514.1.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS IN TOW.
TO THIS POINT,
NO RESISTANCE
HAS BEEN OFFERED.
MY PLAN?
A SHOW OF RESIGNATION.
BALOK'S TRACTOR BEAM
HAS TO BE
A HEAVY DRAIN OF POWER
ON HIS SMALL SHIP.
QUESTION--
WILL HE GROW CARELESS?
CAPTAIN, HE'S PULLING OUT
A LITTLE AHEAD OF US.
HE SNEAK POWERED DOWN A BIT.
OUR SPEED IS DOWN
TO .64 OF LIGHT.
I WANT A RIGHT ANGLE
COURSE.
SHEAR AWAY FROM HIM
NO MATTER WHICH WAY
HE TURNS.
YES, SIR.
MAXIMUM ACCELERATION
WHEN I GIVE THE WORD.
YES, SIR.
ENGAGE.
IT'S A STRAIN, CAPTAIN.
ENGINES ARE OVERLOADING.
MORE POWER.
WE'RE SUPERHEATING.
INTERMIX TEMPERATURE,
7,400 DEGREES.
7,5...
7,6...
8,000 DEGREES.
SHEAR AWAY, MR. BAILEY.
2,000 DEGREES
ABOVE MAXIMUM.
84...
85...
86...
SHE'LL BLOW SOON!
NOW, MR. SULU.
IMPULSE POWER TWO.
WE'RE BREAKING FREE, SIR.
ALL ENGINES STOP.
ALL ENGINES
STOPPED, SIR.
ENGINES NEED WORK BADLY,
CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU HOLD IT HERE
A FEW HOURS?
THAT MAY NOT
BE WISE.
HE GOT A SIGNAL
THROUGH TO
THE MOTHER SHIP.
AND WE'RE NOT HOME YET.
A SIGNAL, CAPTAIN.
IT'S VERY WEAK.
IT'S BALOK.
IT'S A DISTRESS SIGNAL
TO THE FESARIUS.
HIS ENGINES...ARE OUT...
HIS LIFE-SUSTAINING
SYSTEM ISN'T OPERATING.
THE MESSAGE
IS REPEATING, SIR.
ANY REPLY?
NEGATIVE. HIS SIGNAL
IS GROWING WEAK.
SIR, I DOUBT
IF THE MOTHER SHIP
COULD HAVE HEARD IT.
PLOT A COURSE FOR IT,
MR. BAILEY.
FOR IT, CAPTAIN?
DEAD AHEAD.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN
SPEAKING.
FIRST FEDERATION VESSEL
IS IN DISTRESS.
WE'RE PREPARING
TO BOARD IT.
THERE ARE LIVES
AT STAKE--
BY OUR STANDARDS,
ALIEN LIFE--
BUT LIVES NEVERTHELESS.
CAPTAIN OUT.
COURSE PLOTTED
AND LAID IN, SIR.
MR. SCOTT, READY
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AYE, SIR.
MR. SULU, BRING US
TO WITHIN 100 METERS.
AHEAD SLOW.
AHEAD SLOW, SIR.
JIM, DON'T YOU THINK--
WHAT'S THE MISSION
OF THIS VESSEL, DOCTOR?
TO SEEK OUT
AND CONTACT ALIEN LIFE
AND AN OPPORTUNITY
TO DEMONSTRATE
WHAT OUR HIGH-SOUNDING
WORDS MEAN.
ANY QUESTIONS?
I'LL TAKE TWO MEN
WITH ME--
DR. McCOY
TO EXAMINE AND TREAT
THE ALIENS IF NECESSARY,
AND YOU, MR. BAILEY.
SIR?
THE FACE OF THE UNKNOWN.
I THINK I OWE YOU
A LOOK AT IT.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, REQUEST PERMISSION TO--
DENIED.
IF I'M WRONG,
IF IT'S A TRAP,
I WANT YOU HERE.
TRANSPORTER READY?
WELL, YES, SIR,
BUT IT'S RISKY.
WE'RE LOCKED IN
ON WHAT APPEARS
TO BE A MAIN DECK.
AIR SAMPLE?
BREATHABLE.
IN FACT,
A SLIGHTLY HIGHER
OXYGEN CONTENT
THAN OUR OWN.
COMMUNICATOR...
PHASER WEAPON.
THANK YOU, SCOTTY.
READY, DOCTOR?
NO, BUT YOU WON'T
LET THAT STOP YOU.
BEND LOW, GENTLEMEN.
IT READS PRETTY CRAMPED
OVER THERE.
READY TO TRANSPORT.
ENERGIZE.
IT'S A...DUMMY.
A PUPPET OF SOME KIND.
I'M BALOK.
WELCOME ABOARD.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
AND McCOY AND BAILEY.
SIT.
BE COMFORTABLE.
GO AHEAD.
BE SEATED.
WE MUST DRINK.
THIS IS TRANYA.
I HOPE YOU RELISH IT
AS MUCH AS I.
COMMANDER BALOK...
I KNOW, I KNOW.
A THOUSAND QUESTIONS.
BUT FIRST, THE TRANYA.
GENTLEMEN.
AHH...
COMMANDER,
THAT PUPPET...
MY ALTER EGO,
SO TO SPEAK.
IN YOUR CULTURE,
HE WOULD BE MR. HYDE
TO MY JEKYLL.
YOU MUST ADMIT
HE'S EFFECTIVE.
YOU WOULD NEVER HAVE BEEN
FRIGHTENED BY ME.
AND I THOUGHT
MY DISTRESS SIGNAL
QUITE CLEVER.
IT WAS A PLEASURE
TESTING YOU.
TESTING US?
I SEE.
I HAD TO DISCOVER
YOUR REAL INTENTIONS.
BUT YOU PROBED
OUR MEMORY BANKS.
YOUR RECORDS
COULD HAVE BEEN
A DECEPTION
ON YOUR PART.
AND YOUR CREW?
I HAVE NO CREW,
DOCTOR.
I RUN EVERYTHING,
THIS ENTIRE COMPLEX,
FROM THIS SMALL SHIP.
BUT I MISS COMPANY.
CONVERSATION.
EVEN AN ALIEN
WOULD BE WELCOME.
PERHAPS ONE OF YOUR MEN
FOR SOME PERIOD OF TIME.
AN EXCHANGE
OF INFORMATION, CULTURES.
YES.
BOTH OUR CULTURES
WOULD BENEFIT.
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE WE CAN FIND
A VOLUNTEER, MR. BAILEY?
ME, SIR.
I'D LIKE TO VOLUNTEER.
AH.
YOU REPRESENT
EARTH'S BEST, THEN.
NO, SIR, I'M NOT.
I'LL MAKE
PLENTY OF MISTAKES.
BUT YOU'D FIND OUT
MORE ABOUT US
THAT WAY,
AND I'D GET
A BETTER OFFICER
IN RETURN.
I SEE.
WE THINK MUCH ALIKE,
CAPTAIN,
YOU AND I.
NOW, BEFORE I BRING BACK
THE FESARIUS,
LET ME SHOW YOU
MY VESSEL.
IT IS NOT OFTEN
I HAVE THIS PLEASURE.
YES, WE'RE VERY MUCH
ALIKE, CAPTAIN.
BOTH PROUD
OF OUR SHIPS.