Welcome to Starbase
11, Captain.
The Commodore is
waiting to see you,
and he's curious why
you suddenly changed course
and came here.
We received a subspace message
asking us
to divert here immediately.
This base sent no message,
Captain.
You know, Jim, I just
can't understand this.
Mr. Spock received
a transmission
from this starbase.
A message from the former
commander of the Enterprise,
Fleet Captain Pike,
urgently requesting
that we divert here.
Impossible.
If my First Officer states
that he received
a transmission...
17A
Jim, I'm not doubting
anyone's word.
17B
Jose, I...
I'm simply telling
you it's impossible.
Why?
You don't know?
You actually
don't know
what's happened
to Captain Pike?
There's been subspace chatter
about it for months.
I'm sorry to have to be the one
to show you.
He's upstairs in
the medical section.
You ever met
Chris Pike?
We met when he was promoted
to Fleet Captain.
About your age,
a big handsome man,
vital, active.
I took over the Enterprise
from him,
and Spock served with him
for several years.
11 years, four months,
five days.
What's his problem, Commodore?
Inspection tour
of a cadet vessel,
old class-J starship.
One of the baffle
plates ruptured.
The delta-rays?
He went in, bringing
out all those kids
that were still alive.
Just wanted you gentlemen
to be prepared.
MENDEZ:
Captain Pike?
( motorized whir )
Captain, you remember
these gentlemen.
They wanted to visit you.
( two beeps )
Two flashes mean no.
I thought you might make
an exception for them.
( two beeps )
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
Chris, if there's anything
I can do for you...
( two tone )
Captain Pike,
may I remain
for a moment?
( single tone )
You know why I've come, Captain.
It's only six days away
at maximum warp,
and I have it well planned.
( two beeps )
I have never disobeyed
your orders before, Captain...
but this time, I must.
( two beeps )
I know.
I know it is treachery,
and it's mutiny.
But I must do this.
( two beeps )
I have no choice.
Space-- the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission--
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no man has gone before.
( theme song playing )
Once more, Jose.
Spock stated he received
a message for us to come here.
He entered same in his log.
That's all the proof I require.
And what do those
record tapes show?
No message
sent from here.
No message received
by your vessel.
Then I suggest the record tapes
have been deliberately changed.
Oh.
A computer expert can change
record tapes, duplicate voices,
say anything, say nothing.
The fact remains that
your First Officer's
former captain
is hospitalized,
horribly injured
at this base,
and that same First Officer
seems to be the only one
who heard that message
ordering you here.
If he had wanted
to see Captain Pike,
he could have requested
a leave.
I would have granted it!
Well, that's
true, of course!
Who would want
to divert us here?
There's no trouble
in the space sector
we're patrolling now,
no alien problems.
Computer Center.
Chief Humbolt here, sir.
MENDEZ:
Have you rechecked
all the record tapes
on the date in question?
Yes, sir.
Is there any way at all
a message could have been sent
from here without us knowing it?
Negative, Commodore.
We've checked and double-checked
everything possible.
All right.
Start checking the impossible.
Mendez out.
( whirring and beeping )
Oh, have I introduced
Miss Piper, Jim?
Uh-uh.
This is Captain
Kirk, Miss Piper.
I recognized the Captain
immediately.
A mutual friend
described you, sir.
Lieutenant
Helen Johannson?
Helen described...
She merely mentioned
she knew you, sir.
( quietly ):
Oh.
You have something
to report, Miss Piper.
Oh, yes, sir.
I'm afraid
our investigation turned up
very little, Commodore.
There is, of course,
Mr. Spock's years of service
with Captain Pike,
indications of his
extreme loyalty
to this former
commander...
Miss Piper, a Vulcan can
no sooner be disloyal
than he can exist
without breathing.
That goes
for his present commander
as well as his past.
We're forced to consider
every possibility, sir.
We can be certain
Captain Pike could not
have sent a message.
In his condition,
he's under
observation
every minute
of every day.
And totally unable to move, Jim.
His wheelchair
is constructed
to respond to
his brain waves.
Oh, he can turn it,
move it forwards
or backward slightly...
With a flashing light,
he can say yes or no.
MENDEZ:
But that's it, Jim.
That's as much as
that poor devil can do.
His mind is as active
as yours and mine,
but it's trapped
inside a useless,
vegetating body.
He's kept alive mechanically,
a battery-driven heart.
Then there's no way
he could even have asked
for that message to be sent?
COMPUTER
( extremely slow speed):
Starbase Operations.
( very slow speed ):
( slow speed ):
Starbase Operations.
( fast speed ):
( very fast speed ):
Starbase Operations.
( speed slowing ):
( normal speed ):
Starbase Operations.
Starbase Operations
to Enterprise.
Stand by to receive new orders,
Enterprise.
Starbase Operations,
Mr. Hansen.
COMPUTER:
Starbase Operations
to Enterprise.
Stand by to receive new orders.
They are to be fed directly
into the ship's computers.
This is top secret
and scrambled.
Enterprise, standing by.
Request confirmation.
Enterprise to Starbase.
Sir, this is a
security area.
What are you doing here?
I have security
clearance, Chief.
Who gave you clearance?
I haven't been notified.
You're cross-circuiting the...
Whose tapes are these?
UHURA:
Repeat, Enterprise to Starbase.
Orders received.
We need operating confirmation
from the ship's captain.
Come in, Starbase.
Come in, Captain Kirk.
KIRK:
This is Captain Kirk.
You have confirmation,
Miss Uhura.
Hansen here, Captain.
Our destination
has been scramble-fed
into ship's computers.
Uh, how can I handle the helm
if I don't know
where we're going?
KIRK:
Mr. Spock is with me here.
He'll answer all questions.
Kirk out.
This is Mr. Spock.
The ship's computers
will handle the helm
on this voyage, Mr. Hansen.
Course will be computed
and set automatically.
You will not discuss this
with ship's crew
or Starbase personnel.
Do you read?
Acknowledged, sir.
Stand by.
We'll warp out of orbit
in one hour.
( two beeps )
He keeps blinking "no".
"No" to what?
I've tried
questioning him.
He's almost agitated himself
into a coma.
How long will he live?
As long as any of us.
Blast medicine anyway.
We've learned to tie
into every human organ
in the body except
one: the brain.
The brain is what
life is all about.
Now, that man can think
any thought that we can,
and love, hope, dream
as much as we can...
but he can't reach out,
and no one can reach in.
He keeps blinking "no".
"No" to what?
They could question him
for days, weeks,
before they stumble
on the right thing.
Bones...
could this have anything
to do with Spock?
I don't read you
at all, Jim.
What I mean is...
either a message
was received...
It was one of two things.
Either someone sent a message
diverting us here,
or someone on board the ship
lied about receiving it.
Could that someone be Mr. Spock?
Jim, forgetting how well
we both know Spock,
the simple fact
that he's a Vulcan
means he's incapable
of telling a lie.
He is also half-human.
And that half
is completely submerged.
To be caught acting like us
or even thinking like us
would completely
embarrass him.
Someone's interfering with
my command and my ship!
I don't know who it is,
but I mean to find out.
Even you!
If I thought you had
the technical know-how,
I'd suspect you, but
you don't-- Spock does!
He would not make
a false entry...
There's a false entry
in the log right now
which doesn't jibe with
the established facts.
How do you explain that?
I can't, but to question Spock,
of all people? Me, yes.
I could run off half-cocked,
given a good reason.
So could you, but not Spock.
It's impossible.
COMMUNICATOR:
Dr. McCoy,
report to Transporter Control.
Dr. McCoy
to Transporter Control.
McCoy here.
You're needed
aboard the Enterprise, Doctor.
Medical emergency.
Well, what is it?
Sickness, injury? How bad is it?
That's all we have on it,
Doctor: Just "needed aboard".
( sighs )
Probably somebody
discovered a hangnail.
I'll beam up
and let you know, Jim.
"For Eyes Of Starfleet Command
Only."
Oh, I'm certifying
I ordered you to read it.
Know anything at all
about this planet?
KIRK:
What every ship captain knows.
General Order Seven:
"No vessel under any condition,
emergency or otherwise,
is to visit Talos IV."
And to do so is the only
death penalty left on our books.
Only Fleet Command
knows why.
Not even this file
explains that.
But it does name
the only Earth ship
that ever visited
the planet.
The Enterprise.
Commanded
by Captain Christopher Pike.
MENDEZ:
With a half-Vulcan
Science Officer named Spock.
Commodore!
Captain Pike-- he's gone!
Mendez here. What is it?
MAN:
Starship Enterprise, Commodore.
It's warping out of orbit.
Refuses to acknowledge
our signal.
Out of orbit,
Mr. Spock.
Seems strange with
no navigator on duty.
The Enterprise knows
where she's going, Mr. Hansen.
Someone's trying
to hail us, sir.
Maintain radio silence,
Lieutenant.
This is First Officer Spock.
Per Starfleet orders
this date,
I have been placed in temporary
command of the Enterprise.
While our destination is secret,
our mission
is relatively simple.
SPOCK:
Starbase Command has assigned
Captain Kirk medical rest leave
until our return.
His instructions are
that you will obey my orders
as you would his.
First Officer out.
What's going on
around here?
Who said Jim needed
a medical rest leave?
And this call about me being
needed aboard the ship?
I've checked everywhere...
And no one from the ship
made such a call.
That's right.
SPOCK:
Doctor, I regret
they elected to keep
certain things from you.
Will you come with me, please?
What is this, Spock?
Captain, are you all right?
I see that you're
still signaling "no".
Doctor,
one moment, please.
( two beeps )
( single beep )
Kirk to Dr. McCoy.
I'm recording you
this message, Bones,
so there'll be
no misunderstanding.
I'm sorry to have to make it
an order.
You are not to disturb
Captain Pike with any questions.
Simply take good care of him.
Follow Spock's instructions
to the letter.
Kirk out.
( two beeps )
Sir, scanners report
an object following us
about the size of a
Starbase shuttlecraft.
Shall we reverse helm?
Take no action,
Mr. Hansen.
But at our speed,
they'll never catch us.
But in case they
want to reach us...
You have your orders,
Mr. Hansen.
We'll make no contact.
Starbase Shuttlecraft One
to Enterprise.
Come in, please.
Enterprise, Commodore Mendez
and Captain Kirk.
If you read me,
you are ordered to reply.
Repeating it on all
emergency frequencies, Jim.
Spock is headed for
Talos IV, all right.
Pulling ahead of us fast.
Fuel is down to 63.3.
If we turn back now,
we've just got barely enough
to get us back to the base.
Shuttlecraft to
Enterprise, come in.
Shuttlecraft
to Enterprise, come in.
Enterprise, come in!
Library Computer.
Lock onto sensors.
Measure object now following
the Enterprise.
( whirring, clicking )
Computed. Object
is a Class "F" shuttlecraft.
Duranium metal shell,
ion engine power...
Stop. How long before
shuttlecraft's fuel supply
forces return to Starbase?
( whirring clicking )
Computed.
Shuttlecraft is already past
point of safe return.
( low mechanical hum )
( humming winding down )
We coast.
Blast you anyway.
You had no right to come along.
R.H.I.P., Captain.
"Rank hath its privileges".
Two hours of oxygen left.
Wonderful.
Part of me is hoping
that the Enterprise
won't come back for us.
We step on that deck,
Spock is finished,
court-martialed, disgraced.
He's dead... if he makes it
to Talos IV.
Why would he want
to get Pike there?
The Command report stated
Talos contained
absolutely no practical
benefits to mankind.
Spock would have some logical
reason for going there.
Maybe.
Maybe he's just gone mad.
I keep wondering who might be
after us in a shuttlecraft,
and I keep coming up
with the same answers,
but I can't be right,
can I, Mr. Spock?
Computer control, lock onto
shuttlecraft following us.
COMPUTER:
Locked on. Tractor beam ready.
Go to tape Able Seven Baker.
Execute instructions.
Is it the captain, Mr. Spock?
( mechanical whirring )
Sir, the engines
are reversing.
( whirring slowing down )
( whirring stops )
She's brought herself
to a dead stop.
This is the First Officer
speaking.
Security, send an armed team
to the Bridge.
SPOCK:
Transporter Room, stand by
to beam Captain Kirk aboard.
Effective until then,
Lieutenant Hansen
is in operational command.
Sir?
First Officer out.
Doctor, as senior
officer present,
I present myself
to you for arrest.
What?!
The charge is
mutiny, Doctor.
I never received orders
to take command.
Security reporting,
Mr. Spock.
Doctor...
Mr. Spock is, um...
under arrest.
Is confinement
to quarters enough?
Adequate, Doctor.
I'll make no trouble.
( sighs )
Well, confine him.
Yes, sir.
KIRK:
Store our shuttlecraft
on the hangar deck, Mr. Scott.
Beam us directly aboard.
All right, Captain.
Locked onto you.
( trilling beep )
( high-pitched drone )
( droning trails off )
Transferring command
to you, sir.
Accepting command.
Where's Mr. Spock?
In his quarters, sir,
under arrest.
His quarters?
( bosun's whistle sounds )
After what he's done,
Lieutenant?
UHURA:
Captain from Bridge.
The engines are coming on.
Reverse power.
Hold this position.
Tell whoever gave those orders
to report...
Sir, there's nobody up there
giving orders.
Mr. Spock has the computers
running the ship.
Disengage computer control,
Uhura.
We can't disengage, Captain.
The Helm does not respond.
( grumbling )
Computer control,
come in.
( whirring, clicking )
Computer.
Disengage from helm.
Unable to comply.
KIRK:
This is the Captain.
On voice command,
you will override
all contrary instructions.
Voice command:
Disengage from helm.
( whirring, clicking )
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Any such attempt
will cross-circuit
vessel's life supporting system.
Computer control
cannot be disengaged
until vessel reaches
Planet Talos IV.
Captain's Log, Stardate 3012.4.
Despite our best efforts
to disengage computers,
the Enterprise
is still locked on a heading
for the mysterious planet,
Talos IV.
Meanwhile, as required
by Starfleet General Orders,
a preliminary hearing
on Lieutenant Commander Spock
is being convened,
and in all the years
of my service,
this is the most painful moment
I have ever faced.
This hearing is convened.
Mr. Spock...
you are aware of your right
to counsel of your choice?
Sir, I waive counsel.
Further,
I waive rights to this hearing
and request
immediate court-martial.
Request denied.
May I inquire
on what grounds, Captain?
Mutiny requires a trial board
of no less than three
command officers.
Since there are only two
of that rank available...
Sir, I must point out
that there are three officers
of command rank available--
yourself, Commodore Mendez,
and Captain Christopher Pike.
Denied.
Captain Pike
is a complete invalid.
I believe you'll find
he's still on
the active duty list.
We didn't have the heart
to retire him, Jim.
He's got you.
Whatever he's up to,
he's planned it well.
Captain's Log, Stardate 3012.6.
General Court-Martial convened.
Mr. Spock
has again waived counsel
and has entered a plea
of guilty.
Mr. Spock, are you aware
in pleading guilty
that a further charge,
involving the death penalty,
must be held against you
should this vessel
enter the Talos Star Group?
I am.
Why?
What does it accomplish
to go there
or to take Captain Pike there?
I want to know why.
Are your comments
a part of the record, sir?
Yes, it's on
the record!
Thank you.
Request monitor screen
be engaged.
For what purpose?
To comply with the request
you just made, sir--
that I explain the importance
of going to Talos IV.
By asking him why,
you've opened the door
to any evidence
he may wish to present.
Apparently what
he had in mind.
Present your evidence.
Screen on.
This is 13 years ago.
SPOCK:
The Enterprise...
and its commander,
Captain Christopher Pike.
Definitely something
out there, Captain,
headed this way.
Screen off.
Chris, was that really you
on the screen?
( single tone )
That's impossible.
Mr. Spock, no vessel
makes record tapes
in that detail, that perfect.
What were we watching?
I cannot tell you at this time,
sir.
Captain Pike, were
any record tapes of this nature
made during your voyage?
( two beeps, then two more )
The court
is not obliged to view evidence
without knowing its source.
Unless the court asks
a prisoner why, Commodore.
You did ask that question.
You mean I was maneuvered
into asking.
Your evidence is out of order.
I am forced to contest that,
Commodore.
I want to see more.
You have that right, Captain.
But just because the prisoner
is your first officer
and your personal friend...
That has nothing to do with it.
Very well; continue.
Screen on, Mr. Scott.
( high-pitched alarm tones )
Now, there's something
out there.
There's still
something out there.
SPOCK:
As I stated, gentlemen,
this was 13 years ago.
We were on routine patrol
when the ship's sensors
detected something ahead.
At first, we were not certain
what it was.
...coming
at the speed of light.
Collision course.
( high-pitched alarm tones )
The meteorite beam
has not deflected it, Captain.
Evasive maneuvers, sir?
Steady as we go.
It's a radio wave, sir.
We're passing through
an old-style distress signal.
They were keyed
to cause interference
and attract attention this way.
A ship in trouble
making a forced landing, sir.
That's it; no other message.
I have a fix.
It comes from
the Talos Star Group.
We've no ships or Earth
colonies that far out.
Their call letters check
with a survey expedition.
SS Columbia.
Disappeared in that region
approximately 18 years ago.
It would take that long
for a radio beam
to travel from there to here.
Records show the Talos Group
has never been explored.
Solar system similar to Earth.
SPOCK:
11 planets.
Number four seems to be...
Class-M... oxygen atmosphere.
Then they could still be alive,
even after 18 years.
If they survived the crash.
We aren't going to go...
to be certain?
Not without any indication
of survivors, no.
Continue on to the Vega Colony
and take care of our own sick
and injured first.
You have the helm.
Maintain present course.
CREW WOMAN:
Yes, sir.
( communicator chirps )
Royce here.
Drop by my cabin, Doctor.
Ah...
( knock at door )
What's that?
I didn't say
there's anything wrong with me.
I understand we, uh,
picked up a distress signal.
That's right.
Unless we get
anything more positive on it,
it seems to me the condition
of our own crew takes precedent.
I'd like to log the ship's
doctor's opinion, too.
Oh, I concur
with yours, definitely.
You know, good, I'm glad you do,
'cause we're going to stop first
at the Vega Colony
and replace anybody
who needs hospitalization.
And also...
( clinking )
What the devil are you
putting in there, ice?
Who wants a
warm martini?
What makes you think
I need one?
Sometimes a man
will tell his bartender things
he'll never tell his doctor.
What's been on
your mind, Chris,
the fight on Rigel VII?
Shouldn't it be?
My only yeoman and two others
dead, seven injured.
Was there anything
you personally
could have done
to prevent it?
Oh, I should
have smelled trouble
when I saw the swords
and the armor.
Instead of that,
I let myself get trapped
in that deserted fortress
and attacked
by one of their warriors.
Chris, you set standards for
yourself no one could meet.
You treat everyone on board like
a human being except yourself.
And now you're
tired, and you...
You bet I'm tired.
You bet.
I'm tired of being responsible
for 203 lives,
and I'm tired of deciding
which mission is too risky
and which isn't,
and who's going on the landing
party and who doesn't.
And who lives...
and who dies.
Oh, I've had it, Phil.
To the point of finally taking
my advice-- a rest leave?
To the point
of considering resigning.
And do what?
Well, for one thing, go home.
Nice little town with 50 miles
of parkland around it.
Remember I told you
I had two horses?
We used to take some food
and ride out all day.
Oh, that sounds exciting--
ride out with a picnic lunch
every day.
I said that's one place
I might go.
Or I'd, I'd go into business
on Regulus
or on the Orion Colony.
You, an Orion trader,
dealing in green
animal women slaves?
The point is that this
isn't the only life available.
There's a whole galaxy
of things to choose from.
Not for you.
A man either lives life
as it happens to him,
meets it head on and licks it,
or he... turns his back on it
and starts to
wither away.
Now, you're beginning to talk
like a doctor, bartender.
You take your choice.
We both get the same
two kinds of customers:
the living... and the dying.
( inhaling )
( exhaling )
( bosun's whistle sounds )
Mr. Spock here.
We're intercepting
a follow-up message, sir.
There are crash survivors
on Talos.
CREWMAN:
"11 survivors from crash.
"Gravity and oxygen
within limits,
food and water obtainable,
but unless..."
The message faded
at that point, sir.
Address intercraft.
System open.
This is the Captain.
Our destination
is the Talos Star Group,
our time warp factor seven.
( low-pitched whirring )
Course computed
and on the screen.
All decks
have acknowledged, sir.
Engage.
Screen off.
Mr. Spock,
I'm truly amazed
at your technical prowess
in somehow
manufacturing all this.
I congratulate you
on your imagination.
But this is a court
of Space Law, not a theater.
Captain, please tell the court
this is not imagination
nor some clever
photographic record.
Are we seeing the actual events
of 13 years ago?
( single tone )
Yes, gentlemen, on that screen,
as it happened,
the incredible experience
of Captain Christopher Pike
on Talos IV.
If after witnessing this,
the court wishes
to turn this vessel back,
I will release this ship
to manual control.
You're in no position
to bargain.
This is ridiculous.
This man mutinied,
stole your ship,
abducted Captain Pike.
Well, for me,
this has gone far enough.
We still haven't heard
the full story.
I vote to continue.
And I vote we
do not. Deadlock.
It's not a deadlock.
There's still one member of the
trial board to be heard from.
Very well.
Captain Pike,
it's up to you.
Do we continue
under these conditions?
( single tone )
Yes.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Mr. Spock, on trial for mutiny,
has forced the court
to accept unusual evidence.
On our monitor screen,
the voyage of Captain Pike
and the Enterprise
to the one forbidden world
in all the galaxy.
Screen on.
We've settled
into orbit, sir.
Geological lab report
complete, Captain.
Preliminary lab
survey ready, sir.
Spectography?
Our reading shows
an oxygen/nitrogen
atmosphere, sir,
heavy with inert elements,
but well within safety limits.
Gravity?
0.9 of Earth.
Captain. Reflections, sir,
from the planet's surface.
As I read it, they polarize out
as rounded metal bits.
Could be parts of
a spaceship hull.
CAPTAIN:
Equip a landing party
of six.
You feel up to it?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir!
Sorry, Number One.
With little information
on this planet,
we'll have to leave the ship's
most experienced officer here
covering us.
'Course, sir.
( sustained,
low-pitched buzzing )
There's no indication
of problems down there,
but let's not take
any chances.
Yes, sir.
There's a canyon
to the left.
We can set
you down there
completely unobserved.
( low-pitched buzzing )
( loud whirring )
( mechanical screeching )
( sustained whirring )
( trilling hum )
( high-pitched hum )
( hummng trails off )
( high-pitched humming )
( humming stops )
( soft, sustained,
deep humming )
( soft sustained humming )
( humming growing louder )
( deep humming
grows even louder )
( humming quiets )
( humming growing louder )
( sustained deep humming )
Sir.
They're men.
They're humans.
Captain Christopher Pike,
United Space Ship Enterprise.
Dr. Theodore Hess,
American Continent Institute.
Is Earth all right?
Same old Earth,
and you'll see it very soon.
And you won't believe
how fast you can get back.
CREWMAN:
Well, the time barrier's
been broken.
Our new ships can...
This is Vina.
Her parents are dead.
She was born almost
as we crashed.
( communicator chirps )
Enterprise.
WOMAN:
Landing party, come in.
We'll begin transporting
the survivors
and their effects up to you
very shortly.
Quarters
are being prepared, sir.
Have I permission to send out
scouting and scientific
parties now?
Yes, affirmative on the...
You appear to be healthy
and intelligent, Captain.
Prime specimen.
I didn't get that last message,
Captain.
Uh... affirmative on request.
Landing party out.
You must forgive her
choice of words, Captain.
She's lived
her whole life
with a collection
of aging scientists.
If they can, uh,
spare you a moment,
I'd like to make
my medical report.
I think it's time to show
the captain our secret.
Their health is
excellent, almost...
too good.
There's a reason
for our condition,
but we've had
some doubt
if Earth is ready
to learn the secret.
Let the girl show you.
We'll accept
your judgment.
You're tired,
but don't worry.
You'll feel much better soon.
Don't you see it?
Here and here.
I don't understand.
You will.
You're a perfect choice.
( crackling )
Captain!
( communicator chirps )
Spock here.
WOMAN:
Landing party, come in.
There is no survivors
encampment, Number One.
This is all some sort of trap.
We've lost the Captain.
Do you read?
( bosun's whistle sounds )
What is it?
UHURA:
It's for Commodore Mendez.
Fleet signal for you, sir.
Go ahead, Uhura.
Commodore Mendez. Urgent.
Subspace monitors show...
Enterprise
receiving transmissions
from Planet Talos IV
in violation
of Starfleet general orders.
Receiving transmissions
from Talos IV?
KIRK:
Then the images
we've been seeing are...
Are coming from Talos IV, sir.
UHURA:
Captain Kirk is hereby relieved.
You are ordered to assume
command of the Enterprise.
Disable vessel, if necessary,
to prevent further contact.
Message signed:
Comsol, Starfleet Command.
Mr. Spock, you're aware
of the orders
regarding any contact
with Talos IV.
You have deliberately
invited the death penalty.
You've not only finished
yourself, Spock,
but you finished
your captain as well.
The Commodore must be aware
that Captain Kirk
knew nothing of this.
And you're aware that
a captain is responsible
for everything
that occurs on his ship.
I order you to return this
vessel back to manual control.
Sir... I respectfully decline.
Very well.
You've earned the consequences.
The court is in recess.
Do you know what
you're doing?
Have you lost your mind?
Captain...
Jim, please... don't stop me.
Don't let him stop me.
It's your career
and Captain Pike's life.
You must see
the rest of the transmission.
Lock him up.