Personal log,
stardate 3013. 1.
I find it hard to believe
the events of the past 24 hours
or the plea of Mr. Spock
standing general court-martial.
How do you plead to the charge
of unlawfully taking command
of this starship?
Guilty.
Of sabotaging the computers
of this vessel
and locking it
on a course
for planet Talos IV?
Guilty.
And of forcibly
attempting
to transport Captain Pike
to that planet?
Guilty.
Why? Why does Spock
want to take to that forbidden
world his former captain,
mutilated by
a recent space disaster,
now a shell of a man,
unable to speak or move?
The only answer
Spock would give
was on
the hearing-room screen.
How Spock would do this,
he refused to explain,
but there, before our eyes,
actual images
from 13 years ago
of Captain Pike as he was
when he commanded
this vessel,
of Spock in those days,
and of how the Enterprise
had become the first
and only starship
to visit Talos IV.
They had received
a distress signal
from that planet
and discovered there,
still alive
after many years,
the survivors
of a missing vessel,
only to find
it was all an illusion--
No survivors...
no encampment...
it was all a trap
set by a race of beings
who could make a man
believe he was seeing
anything they wished
him to see,
and Captain Pike was gone,
a prisoner for some
unknown purpose.
The images we've
been seeing are--
Are coming
from Talos IV.
You're aware of the orders
regarding any contact
with Talos IV.
You have deliberately invited
the death penalty.
Do you know
what you're doing?
Have you
lost your mind?
Captain.
Jim, please.
Don't stop me.
Don't let him stop me.
It's your career
and Captain Pike's life.
You must see the rest
of the transmission.
Space--
the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission--
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where
no man has gone before.
The court-martial
of Mr. Spock
has been convened
in closed session.
Despite all we can do,
images continue to be
transmitted to us
from Talos IV.
Starfleet has ordered no
contact with Talos IV.
They made no exceptions.
You have no choice, sir.
I'm sorry.
The keeper has taken
control of our screen.
Do you understand, sir?
As you saw before,
Captain Pike had been
knocked unconscious
and captured by
the Talosians.
Can you hear me?
My name is Christopher Pike,
commander of the space
vehicle Enterprise
from the stellar group
at the other end
of this galaxy.
Our intentions
are peaceful.
Can you understand me?
It appears, Magistrate,
that the intelligence
of the specimen
is shockingly limited.
This is no surprise,
since his vessel
was baited here so easily
with a simulated
message.
As you can read
in its thoughts,
it is only now
beginning to suspect
that the survivors
and encampment
were a simple illusion
we placed in their minds.
You're not speaking,
yet I can hear you.
Note the confusion
as it reads our
thought transmissions.
All right, then,
telepathy.
You can read my mind.
I can read yours.
Now, unless you
want my ship
to consider capturing me
an unfriendly act--
You now see the primitive
fear/threat reaction.
The specimen is about to boast
of his strength,
the weaponry
of his vessel,
and so on.
Next...
frustrated into a need
to display
physical prowess,
the creature
will throw himself
against
the transparency.
If you were in here,
wouldn't you test the strength
of these walls, too?
There's a way out
of any cage,
and I'll find it.
Despite its frustration,
the creature
appears more adaptable
than our specimens
from other planets.
We can soon begin
the experiment.
The inhabitants
of this planet
must live deep underground,
probably manufacture food
and other needs down there.
Our tests indicate
the planet surface,
without considerably more
vegetation or some animals,
is simply too barren
to support life.
So we just thought
we saw survivors there.
Exactly.
An illusion placed
in our minds
by this planet's
inhabitants.
It was
a perfect illusion.
They had us seeing just
what we wanted to see--
human beings
who had survived
with dignity and bravery,
everything
entirely logical,
right down to the building
of the camp,
the tattered clothing,
everything.
Let's be sure we understand
the danger of this.
The inhabitants
of this planet
can read our minds,
can create illusions out
of a person's own thoughts,
memories, and experiences,
even out of a person's
own desires,
illusions
just as real and solid
as this table top
and just as impossible
to ignore.
It's Captain Pike
they've got.
He needs help.
If we buzz about
down there,
we may find their mental
power is so great,
they could swat
this ship like a fly.
That entry resisted
hand lasers.
We'll transmit
the ship's power against it,
enough to blast
half a continent.
Engineering deck will rig
to transmit ship's power.
We'll try blasting
through that metal.
Thousands of us
are already probing
the creature's thoughts,
Magistrate.
We find excellent
memory capacity.
I read most strongly
a recent death struggle
in which it fought
to protect its life.
We will begin with this,
giving the specimen
something more interesting
to protect.
Come on.
We must
hide ourselves.
Come.
Hurry.
It's deserted.
There'll be weapons
and perhaps food.
This is Rigel 7.
Please, we must
hide ourselves.
I was in a cage, a cell,
in some kind of a zoo.
I must still be there.
Come on.
They've reached
into my mind
and taken the memory
of somewhere I've been.
[ Grrr ]
The Kaylar!
It's starting
just as it happened
two weeks ago.
[ Grrr ]
Except for you.
A brilliant deduction
by Captain Pike, gentlemen.
Yes, he was still
inside his cell,
but knowing that
couldn't help him.
The Talosians
controlled his brain.
And could make him live
any place, any time,
any situation
they wished.
He would see,
taste, suffer
with the same reality
as you gentlemen sitting there.
Longer hair,
different dress,
but it is you,
the one the survivors
call Vina.
Roar!
Or rather
the image of Vina.
But why you again?
Why didn't they create
a different girl?
[ Grrr ]
Quick.
If you attack
while it's not looking...
But it's
only a dream.
[ Grrr ]
You have to kill him
as you did here before.
Tell my jailers I won't
go along with it.
I'm not an animal performing
for its supper.
What ever you call this,
you'll feel it.
That's what matters.
You'll feel every moment
of what happens to you.
[ Clanging ]
[ Grrr ]
Oh!
Aah!
[ Grrr ]
Ohh!
Aah!
[ Grrr ]
It's over.
Why have they
stopped the images?
Because they know
that Captain Pike is fatigued.
We can reconvene later.
Then they care
about the captain?
They want him back
alive, sir.
I demand to know why.
If you'll be patient,
the answers--
You're forgetting
you're on trial, Spock.
You will answer
all questions put to you.
My answer to your question
would be quite unbelievable.
I regret we'll have to wait
and see it there.
Personal log,
stardate 3013.2.
Reconvening court-martial
of Mr. Spock
and the strangest
trial evidence
ever heard
aboard a starship.
From the mysterious planet
now only one hour
ahead of us,
the story of Captain Pike's
imprisonment there.
Why are you here?
To please you.
Are you real?
As real as you wish.
No. No.
No, that's not
any answer.
I've never met you before,
never even imagined you.
Perhaps they made me
out of dreams
you've forgotten.
And dress you in the same
metal fabric they wear?
I can wear
whatever you wish
or be anything you wish.
So they can see how
their specimen performs?
They want to
see how I react?
Don't you
have a--a dream,
something you've always
wanted very badly?
Or do they do more
than just watch me?
Do they...
feel with me, too?
You can have whatever
dream you want.
I can become anything,
any woman you--
you've ever imagined.
You can have
anything you want
in the whole universe.
Let me...
please you.
Yes. Yes,
you can please me.
You can tell me
about them.
How can I keep them
from probing my mind,
from using my thoughts
against me?
Does that frighten you?
Does that mean
there is a way?
You're a fool.
Since you're not real,
there's not much point
in continuing
this conversation, is there?
All circuits engaged,
Mr. Spock.
Standing by,
Number One.
Take cover.
10...
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Increase to full power!
Can you give us any more?
Our circuits are
beginning to heat.
We'll have to cease power.
Disengage.
The top of that knoll
should have been sheared off
the first second.
Maybe it was.
I tried to explain.
Their power of illusion
is so great,
we can't be sure
of anything we do,
of anything we see.
Perhaps if you
asked me some questions
I could answer.
How far can they
control my mind?
If I tell you,
then will you pick
some dream you've had
and let me
live it with you?
Perhaps.
They--they can't actually
make you do anything
you don't want to do.
But they try to trick me
with their illusions.
They can punish you when
you're not cooperative.
Did they ever live
on the surface of this planet?
Why did they
go underground?
War, thousands
of centuries ago.
That's why it's
so barren up there?
The planet's only now becoming
able to support life again.
So the Talosians
who came underground
found life
limited here
and they concentrated on
developing their mental power.
But they found
it's a trap...
like a narcotic,
because when dreams
become more important
than reality,
you give up travel,
building, creating.
You even forget how
to repair the machines
left behind
by your ancestors.
You just sit,
living and reliving
other lives
left behind
in the thought record.
Or sit probing minds of
zoo specimens like me.
You're better
than a theater to them.
They create
the illusion for you.
They watch you react,
feel your emotions.
They have a whole
collection of specimens,
descendants of life
brought back long ago
from all over this part
of the galaxy.
Which means they had
to have more than one
of each animal.
Please.
They'll need
a pair of humans.
Where will they
get the Earth woman?
You said that if
I answered your questions--
That was a bargain
with something
that didn't exist.
You said you weren't
real, remember?
I'm a woman as real
and as human as you are.
We are like Adam and Eve.
If we--
Don't! Please!
Don't punish me!
I'll die!
Ohh! Aah!
An Earth woman?
You were captured
as breeding stock?
Why?
Just to maintain
a supply of zoo specimens?
Much more, Captain.
The vial contains a nourishing
protein complex.
Is the keeper
actually communicating
with one of his animals?
If the form and the color
is not appealing,
it can appear as any food
you wish to visualize.
And if I prefer...
To starve?
You overlook
the unpleasant alternative
of punishment.
Aah!
[ Screaming ]
From a fable you
once heard in childhood.
You will now consume
the nourishment.
Why not...
just put irresistible
hunger in my mind?
Because you can't,
can you?
You do have limitations,
don't you?
If you continue
to disobey,
from deeper
in your mind,
there are things
even more unpleasant.
That's very interesting.
Now to the female.
You were startled.
Weren't you
reading my mind?
As you've conjectured,
an Earth vessel did
crash on our planet,
but with only
a single survivor.
Let's stay
on the first subject.
All I wanted
for that moment
was to get my hands
around your neck.
We repaired
the survivor's injuries
and found the species
interesting.
Do primitive thoughts
put up a block
you can't read through?
It became necessary
to attract a mate.
All right. Let's talk
about the girl.
You've gone out
of your way
to make her attractive,
to make me
feel protective.
This is necessary
in order to perpetuate
the species.
Seems more important
to you now
that I begin to accept
her and like her.
We wish our specimens
to be happy
in their new life.
Assuming that's a lie,
why would you want me
attracted to her,
so I'll feel love
in a husband-wife relationship?
That would be necessary
only if you intend
to build a family group
or perhaps a whole
human community.
With the female now
properly conditioned.
You mean
properly punished!
I'm the one who's
not cooperating!
Why don't you punish me?
First, an emotion
of protectiveness.
Now one of sympathy.
Excellent.
You want some coffee,
dear?
I left the thermos
hooked to my saddle.
[ Whinny ]
Tango!
You old devil, you.
Uh, I'm sorry I
don't have any sug--
Well, they think
of everything, don't they?
Is it good to be home?
They read our minds
very well.
Home,
anything else I want
if I cooperate,
is that it?
It turned out to be
a lovely day, didn't it?
You're home.
You can even stay
if you want.
But we're not here,
neither of us.
We're in a menagerie,
a cage!
No.
I can't help either one of us
if you won't give me a chance
Now, you told me once
they used illusions
as a narcotic.
They couldn't repair
their ancestors' machines.
Is that
why they want us,
to build a colony
of slaves?
Stop it.
Don't you care what
they'll do to us?
In my cage,
it seemed for two minutes
our keeper couldn't
read my thoughts.
Do emotions like hate,
keeping hate
in your mind,
does that block off
our mind from them?
Yes.
They can't read through
primitive emotions,
but you can't keep it up
for long enough.
I've tried.
They keep at you and at you
year after year,
tricking
and punishing.
And they've won.
They own me.
I know you must
hate me for that.
Oh, no.
I don't hate you.
I can guess
what it was like.
But that's not enough.
Don't you see?
They read my thoughts,
my feelings,
my dreams of what would be
a perfect man.
That's why
they picked you.
I can't help
but love you.
And they expect you
to feel the same way.
If they can
read my mind,
then they know I'm
attracted to you.
I was from the very first
moment I saw you.
You were like
a wild little animal.
I'm beginning to see
why none of this
has worked for you.
You've been home,
and fighting as on Rigel--
That's not new
to you, either.
A person's
strongest dreams
are about
what he can't do.
Yes, a ship's captain,
always having to be
so formal,
so decent and honest
and proper.
You must wonder
what it would be like
to forget all that.
[ Flutes And Drums Play ]
Nice place you have
here, Mr. Pike.
Vina?
That's Vina again,
as the green Orion
slave girl?
[ Mendez ]
They're like animals--
vicious, seductive.
They say no human male
can resist them.
[ Kirk ]
Strange evidence from the past,
how the Talosians,
planning to breed
a society of human slaves,
tempted Captain Pike
with the Earth woman
they held in captivity.
As she appeared to him
in many forms,
each more exciting
than the last,
Pike was beginning
to weaken.
Suppose you had
all of space to choose from
and this was only
one small sample.
Wouldn't you say
it was worth a man's soul?
You all know
the situation.
We're hoping to
transport down inside
the Talosian community.
If our measurements
and readings
are an illusion also,
one could find oneself
materialized
inside solid rock.
Nothing will be said
if any volunteer
wants to back out.
The women!
Captain.
Captain...
No! Let me finish!
But we were
a party of six.
We were the only ones
transported.
It's not fair.
You don't need them.
They don't work.
They were fully charged
when we left.
It's dead. I can't
make this thing work.
What is it?
Don't say anything.
I'm filling my mind
with a picture
of beating their huge,
misshapen heads to pulp,
thoughts so primitive
they black out everything else.
I'm filling my mind
with hate.
How long can you
block your thoughts?
A few minutes,
an hour?
How can that help?
Leave him alone.
He doesn't need you.
He's already picked me.
Picked her?
For what?
I don't understand.
Now, there's a fine choice
for intelligent offspring.
Offspring...
as in children?
Offspring as in,
he's Adam.
Is that it?
You're no better choice.
They'd have more luck
crossing him with a computer.
Shall we do some
time computation?
There was a Vina listed
on that expedition
as an adult crewman.
Adding 18 years
to your age then--
[ Door Opens ]
It's not fair.
I did what you asked.
Since you resist
the present specimen,
you now have
a selection.
I'll break out of this zoo
somehow and get to you.
Is your blood red
like ours?
I'm going to find out.
Each of the two
new specimens
has qualities
in her favor.
The female
you call Number One
has the superior mind
and would produce
highly intelligent children.
All I want to do
is get my hands on you.
Can you read
these thoughts--
images of hate,
killing?
The other new arrival has
considered you unreachable
but now realizes
this has changed.
The factors in her favor
are youth and strength
plus unusually strong
female drives.
You'll find my thoughts
more interesting,
thoughts so primitive
you can't understand.
Emotions so--
Oh!
Wrong thinking
is punishable.
Right thinking
will be as quickly rewarded.
You will find it an
effective combination.
Captain--
No.
No. Don't help me.
I have to concentrate.
They can't read
through hate.
You hold still,
or I'll--
Don't hurt them.
They don't mean to be evil.
I've had some samples
of how good they are.
[ Grrrr ]
You stop this illusion,
or I'll twist your head off.
All right.
Now, you try
one more illusion,
you try anything at all,
and I'll break your neck.
Your ship...
release me,
or we'll destroy it.
He's not bluffing,
Captain.
They can make your crew
work the wrong controls
or push any button
it takes to destroy your ship.
I'm going to gamble
you're too intelligent
to kill
for no reason at all.
On the other hand,
I've got a reason.
I bet you've created
an illusion this laser is empty.
I think it blasted a hole
that you keep us from seeing.
Want me to test my theory out
on your head?
Captain.
Seems the Talosians
have deserted you.
Gentlemen,
a moment, please.
Well, Mr. Spock?
May I have
your verdict?
Signal you want
them to wait.
Captain, please.
It's your life now...
at least
a chance for life.
You keep talking about life,
How? As a prisoner,
caged, a zoo specimen,
living the illusions
that amuse his keepers?
No, Captain.
there's more to it.
Watch.
Guilty, yes or no,
Captain?
Yes.
I must also vote
guilty as charged.
And you, Captain?
Guilty...
as charged.
Security control
affirmative.
Stand to,
forward phaser.
Aft scanner
to bridge.
Bridge to commander.
Mendez here.
Sir, we're entering
orbit Talos IV.
Talos controls
the vessel now, sir,
as they 13 did years ago.
You've asked me why.
You'll see the answer now.
Make contact,
Number One.
They kept us
from seeing this, too.
We cut through
and never knew it.
Captain.
As you see,
your attempt to escape
accomplished nothing.
I want to contact
our ship.
You're now
on the surface
where we
wished you to be.
With the female
of your choice,
you will now begin
carefully guided lives.
And start
by burying you?
That is your choice.
To help you reclaim
the planet's surface,
our zoological gardens
will furnish a variety
of plant life.
I'll make a deal
with you.
You and your life
for the lives
of these two Earth women.
Show proof our
ship's all right,
send these two back,
and I'll stay
with Vina.
It's wrong to create
a race of humans
to live as slaves.
Is this a deception?
Do you intend
to destroy yourselves?
What's that?
The weapon
is building up an overload,
a forced chamber explosion.
You still have time
to get underground.
Well, go on!
Just to show you how primitive
humans are, Talosian,
you go with her.
If--if you all think
it's this important,
then...
I can't go, either.
I suppose if they
have one human being,
they might try again.
Wait.
Their method of storing records
is crude and consumed much time.
Are you prepared
to assimilate it?
We had not believed
this possible.
The customs and
history of your race
show a unique hatred
of captivity.
Even when it's pleasant
and benevolent,
you prefer death.
This makes you too violent
and dangerous a species
for our needs.
He means that...
they can't use you.
You're free to go
back to the ship.
And that's it.
No apologies...
you captured one of us,
threatened all of us.
Your unsuitability
has condemned the Talosian race
to eventual death.
Is this not sufficient?
No other specimen
has shown your adaptability.
You were our last hope.
But wouldn't
some form of trade...
mutual cooperation...
Your race would learn
our power of illusion
and destroy
itself, too.
[ Intercom Whistles ]
Captain, we have
transporter control now.
Let's get back
to the ship.
I can't.
I can't go with you.
Sir, it just came on.
We can't shut the power off.
- [ Intercom Whistles ]
- Mr. Spock here.
All power has come on.
The helm is answering
to control.
The captain.
You see why
I can't go with you.
This is the female's
true appearance.
They found me
in the wreckage, dying,
a lump of flesh.
They rebuilt me.
Everything works.
But they had never
seen a human.
They had no guide
for putting me
back together.
It was necessary
to convince you
her desire to stay
is an honest one.
You'll give her back
her illusion of beauty?
And more.
Mr. Spock, the system
is coming on again.
What's happened
to Vina?
Isn't she
coming with us?
No.
No, and I agreed
with her reasons.
All decks prepare
for hyperdrive.
All decks
are ready, sir.
Engage.
Commodore,
don't you think that--
What you now seem to hear,
Captain Kirk,
are my thought
transmissions.
The commodore was
never aboard your vessel.
His presence there
and in the shuttlecraft
was an illusion.
Mr. Spock had related to us
your strength of will.
It was thought the fiction
of a court-martial
would divert you
from too soon regaining
control of your vessel.
Captain Pike is welcome
to spend the rest
of his life with us,
unfettered
by his physical body.
The decision is yours...
and his.
Mr. Spock,
even if regulations
are explicit,
you could have come to me
and explained.
Ask you to face
the death penalty, too?
One of us
was enough, Captain.
[ Intercom Whistles ]
Yes.
[ Uhura ]
Message from Starbase 11, sir.
"Received images
from Talos IV.
"In view of historic
importance of Captain Pike
"in space exploration,
"General Order 7
prohibiting contact Talos IV
"is suspended
this occasion.
"No action contemplated
against Spock.
"Proceed
as you think best.
Signed, Mendez, J.I.,
Commodore, Starbase."
Chris...
do you
want to go there?
Mr. Spock...
would you care
to take Captain Pike
to the transporter room...
see him off?
Thank you, sir.
For both of us.
Uh, Mr. Spock,
when you're finished,
I want to talk to you.
This regrettable tendency
you've been showing lately
towards flagrant
emotionalism--
I see no reason
to insult me, sir.
I believe I've been
completely logical
about
the whole affair.
[ Talosian ]
Captain Kirk...
Captain Pike
has an illusion,
and you have reality.
May you find your way
as pleasant.