INTERESTING.
AN ARKTURIAN MACBETH.
WATCH HIM.
WATCH MACBETH.
IS HE DEAD?
SPEAK.
IS KING DUNCAN DEAD?
ALL GREAT NEPTUNE'S
OCEAN,
WASH THIS BLOOD
CLEAN FROM MY HANDS.
THAT VOICE.
HOW IS IT WITH ME, WHEN
EVERY NOISE APPALLS ME?
THAT MAN
ON THE STAGE.
I'M CERTAIN OF IT.
THAT'S KODOS...
THE EXECUTIONER.
PLUCK'D OUT MINE EYES!
Kirk: SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 2817.6.
STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE" DIVERTED
FROM SCHEDULED COURSE.
PURPOSE--TO CONFIRM DISCOVERY
BY DR. THOMAS LEIGHTON
OF AN EXTRAORDINARY
NEW SYNTHETIC FOOD
WHICH WOULD TOTALLY END
THE THREAT OF FAMINE
ON SIGNIA MINOR,
A NEARBY EARTH COLONY.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME YOU'VE
CALLED ME 3 LIGHT-YEARS
OFF MY COURSE
JUST TO ACCUSE AN ACTOR
OF BEING KODOS?
HE IS KODOS.
I'M SURE OF IT.
YOU SAID YOU DISCOVERED
A NEW FOOD CONCENTRATE.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO PUT IN MY LOG,
THAT YOU LIED, THAT YOU
DIVERTED A STARSHIP
WITH FALSE INFORMATION?
YOU'RE NOT ONLY IN TROUBLE,
YOU'VE PUT ME
IN TROUBLE, TOO.
I DID IT
TO TRAP KODOS!
KODOS...
IS DEAD.
IS HE?
IS ANYONE SURE?
A BODY BURNED
BEYOND RECOGNITION?
TOM,
THE AUTHORITIES CLOSED
THE BOOK ON THAT CASE
YEARS AGO.
THEN LET'S REOPEN IT.
JIM, 4,000 PEOPLE
WERE BUTCHERED.
MARTHA, WILL YOU
TELL HIM?
I CAN'T TELL HIM
ANYTHING, JIM.
HE'S BEEN LIKE THIS
SINCE THE COMPANY
OF ACTORS ARRIVED.
KODOS IS DEAD.
I'M SATISFIED
WITH THAT.
WELL, I'M NOT.
I REMEMBER HIM.
THAT VOICE.
THE BLOODY THING HE DID.
JIM...
JIM, I NEED YOUR HELP.
THERE WERE ONLY
8 OR 9 OF US
WHO ACTUALLY SAW KODOS.
I WAS ONE.
YOU'RE ANOTHER.
IF HE'S TO BE EXPOSED--
HE'S DEAD.
THEN
IT WILL BE A GHOST
MARTHA AND I RECEIVE
IN OUR HOME TONIGHT.
I INVITED
THE ENTIRE COMPANY
TO A COCKTAIL PARTY.
I HAVE TO BE SURE.
I HAVE TO GET
BACK TO MY SHIP
AND FIGURE OUT
HOW I'M GONNA
ENTER ALL THIS
IN MY LOG.
TOM. MARTHA.
Electronic voice:
LIBRARY COMPUTER.
HISTORY FILES.
SUBJECT--
FORMER GOVERNOR
KODOS OF TARSUS IV,
ALSO KNOWN AS KODOS
THE EXECUTIONER.
AFTER THAT,
BACKGROUND ON ACTOR
ANTON KARIDIAN.
WORKING.
KODOS THE EXECUTIONER.
SUMMARY--
GOVERNOR OF TARSUS IV
20 EARTH YEARS AGO.
INVOKED MARTIAL LAW.
SLAUGHTERED
50% OF POPULATION
EARTH COLONY
THAT PLANET.
BURNED BODY FOUND
WHEN EARTH FORCES ARRIVED.
NO POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
CASE CLOSED.
DETAILED INFORMATION
FOLLOWS.
ON STARDATE 2794.7--
STOP.
KODOS--
INFORMATION
ON ANTON KARIDIAN.
DIRECTOR AND STAR
OF TRAVELING
COMPANY OF ACTORS
SPONSORED BY GALACTIC
CULTURAL EXCHANGE PROJECT.
TOURING OFFICIAL
INSTALLATIONS
LAST 9 YEARS.
HAS DAUGHTER LENORE,
19 YEARS OLD--
STOP. GIVE COMPARATIVE
IDENTIFICATION
BETWEEN
THE ACTOR KARIDIAN
AND GOVERNOR KODOS.
NO IDENTIFICATION
RECORDS AVAILABLE
ON ACTOR ANTON KARIDIAN.
GIVE INFORMATION
ON ACTOR KARIDIAN
PRIOR TO KODOS'S DEATH.
NO INFORMATION
AVAILABLE
ANTON KARIDIAN
PRIOR TO
20 YEARS AGO.
PHOTOGRAPH KODOS.
PHOTOGRAPH KARIDIAN.
NOW PHOTOGRAPH BOTH.
MR. SPOCK.
YOU KNOW DR. LEIGHTON,
DON'T YOU?
WOULD YOU SAY
HE'S GIVEN TO FANTASY?
A GOOD EMPIRICAL
RESEARCH SCIENTIST.
STEADY, REPUTABLE,
OCCASIONALLY BRILLIANT.
WITH A VERY LONG MEMORY.
I HAVE
NO INFORMATION
ON THAT, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE READY
TO LEAVE ORBIT.
WE'LL DELAY DEPARTURE
FOR A TIME.
I'M BEAMING BACK DOWN
TO THE PLANET AGAIN.
[LAUGHTER]
WHERE'S TOM?
HE WENT TO TOWN.
HE CALLED.
HE'S ON HIS WAY BACK.
THE OTHERS
ARE ON THE PATIO.
I TAKE IT YOU'RE
THE WELCOMING COMMITTEE.
IS THAT FOR ME?
WHY NOT?
I SAW YOUR
PERFORMANCE TONIGHT.
MAY I EXTEND
MY APPRECIATION?
MY FATHER WILL BE
DELIGHTED, MR...
MR...
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK,
STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
OH. WE'RE HONORED.
I HAD HOPED
TO MEET YOUR FATHER
HERE TONIGHT PERSONALLY.
I'M SORRY,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
HE HAS A RIGID RULE
ABOUT THAT.
HE NEVER SEES ANYONE
PERSONALLY,
AND HE NEVER
ATTENDS PARTIES.
AN ACTOR TURNING AWAY
HIS ADMIRERS?
VERY UNUSUAL.
KARIDIAN IS A MOST
UNUSUAL MAN.
YOU SAW "MACBETH."
THAT WAS MY FATHER.
WELL, THEN I'LL TALK
TO LADY MACBETH.
SO, CAPTAIN
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
INTERESTING.
SO, LADY MACBETH.
WHAT'S YOUR NEXT MOVE?
WE PLAY TWO PERFORMANCES
AT BENECIA
IF THE "ASTRAL QUEEN"
CAN GET US THERE.
SHE'S A GOOD SHIP.
THANK YOU.
YOU WERE VERY IMPRESSIVE
AS LADY MACBETH.
THANK YOU.
AND AS LENORE KARIDIAN?
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
LENORE.
I'D LIKE
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
YOU MEAN PROFESSIONALLY?
NOT NECESSARILY.
I THINK I'D LIKE THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE MUST KEEP A SCHEDULE.
YOU DON'T HAVE A SCHEDULE
NOW, DO YOU?
YOU MEAN LEAVE?
BUT I'VE ONLY
JUST ARRIVED.
SO HAVE I.
AND YOU HATE
TO OVERSTAY
A WELCOME.
EXACTLY.
WHY NOT?
GOOD.
I'LL MAKE OUR APOLOGIES
TO OUR HOSTESS.
I'LL MEET YOU OUTSIDE.
TIRED OF WALKING?
NO. JUST THINKING.
ABOUT WHAT?
AT THE PARTY, YOU WERE
SUCH A BRASH YOUNG MAN.
AND NOW?
NOW SOMEHOW DIFFERENT.
NOT A SHIP'S CAPTAIN
WITH ALL THOSE PEOPLE
TO BE STRONG
AND CONFIDENT
IN FRONT OF.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE
REALLY VERY DEAR,
AREN'T YOU?
IN SOME WAYS...
VERY LONELY.
IT'S TOM LEIGHTON.
HE'S DEAD.
TOM...
AT LEAST
HE HAS PEACE NOW.
HE NEVER REALLY
HAD THAT BEFORE.
OH,
WHY WAS TOM KILLED
IF WHAT HE SUSPECTED
WASN'T TRUE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'LL TRY AND FIND OUT.
OH, JIM.
HOW I'LL MISS HIM.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
Uhura: BRIDGE
HERE, CAPTAIN.
PUT ME THROUGH
TO CAPTAIN JOHN DALEY
OF THE "ASTRAL QUEEN"
IN ORBIT STATION,
AND PUT IT ON SCRAMBLE,
WILL YOU?
CAPTAIN DALEY'S
ON, SIR.
JOHN. JIM KIRK.
Daley: HI, JIM.
CAN YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
I OWE YOU A DOZEN.
JUST ASK.
DON'T MAKE
YOUR PICKUP HERE.
YOU MEAN STRAND
ALL THOSE ACTORS?
I'LL PICK THEM UP.
AND IF THERE'S
ANY TROUBLE,
IT'LL BE
MY RESPONSIBILITY.
WILL DO.
ANYTHING ELSE?
JUST KEEP THIS
BETWEEN THE TWO OF US
AND ACCEPT MY THANKS.
OVER AND OUT.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
Uhura: BRIDGE
HERE, CAPTAIN.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
READY TO BEAM UP.
AHA.
READY TO RESUME
COURSE, CAPTAIN.
I THINK WE'RE DUE
FOR A PICKUP.
WHAT KIND,
PERSONNEL? CARGO?
CAPTAIN?
A MISS KARIDIAN HAS BEEN
TRANSPORTED ABOARD SHIP.
SHE REQUESTS PERMISSION
TO SEE YOU.
TELL HER TO COME
UP TO THE BRIDGE.
Uhura: ESCORT MISS KARIDIAN
TO THE BRIDGE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
THIS LADY
WAS COMING ABOARD?
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I DIDN'T THINK WE'D BE
MEETING AGAIN SO SOON.
YOU PROBABLY
WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
IF I TOLD YOU
I ARRANGED IT.
NO, BUT IT'S
A DELIGHTFUL THOUGHT.
CAPTAIN, I'M AFRAID
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
WE'VE BEEN STRANDED.
IT SEEMS
THAT OUR TRANSPORTATION
HAS CANCELED OUT
ON US.
CAN'T YOU MAKE
OTHER ARRANGEMENTS?
WELL, YES,
BUT NOT IN TIME.
YOU SEE, OUR SCHEDULE
IS LIKE A CHAIN.
ONE BREAK
AND IT ALL COLLAPSES.
BE A SHAME
IF THAT HAPPENED.
IF EVER WE NEEDED
A GOOD SAMARITAN.
WELL, I...
I APPEAL TO YOU.
THE REGULATIONS
ARE VERY CLEAR
ABOUT TAKING ON
PASSENGERS.
I'LL MAKE A BARGAIN
WITH YOU, CAPTAIN.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT
TO TRADE?
SPECIAL PERFORMANCE
FOR THE CREW
IN EXCHANGE FOR A LIFT.
YOU MAKE IT SOUND
VERY INTERESTING.
THE CREW'S BEEN ON PATROL
FOR A LONG TIME.
THEY COULD USE
A BREAK IN THE...
MONOTONY.
THEN YOU'LL DO IT?
YOU'VE GOT ME BACKED
INTO A CORNER.
THE MEN WOULD
NEVER FORGIVE ME
IF I DEPRIVED THEM
OF YOUR PERFORMANCE
AND YOUR PRESENCE.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I'M ETERNALLY GRATEFUL.
I'LL GET THE COMPANY
READY.
THIS MEANS
SO MUCH TO THEM.
MR. SPOCK,
PREPARE
TO LEAVE ORBIT
AS SOON AS
THE KARIDIAN COMPANY
IS ABOARD THE SHIP.
MAY I INQUIRE AS TO
OUR COURSE, CAPTAIN?
BENECIA COLONY.
BENECIA COLONY
IS 8 LIGHT-YEARS
OFF OUR COURSE.
IF MY MEMORY
NEEDS REFRESHING,
MR. SPOCK,
I'LL ASK YOU FOR IT.
IN THE MEANTIME,
FOLLOW MY ORDERS.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 2818.9.
THERE ARE MANY QUESTIONS
IN MY MIND--
TOO MANY, PERHAPS--
ABOUT THE ACTOR KARIDIAN
AND HIS DAUGHTER.
FOR PERSONAL REASONS,
I'M ALMOST AFRAID
TO LEARN THE ANSWERS.
MR. SPOCK,
E.T.A.
THE BENECIA COLONY.
WE'LL ARRIVE
STARDATE 2825.3, CAPTAIN,
APPROXIMATELY 1500
BENECIA TIME.
Electronic voice:
LIBRARY COMPUTER.
DATA ON
QUESTIONS SUBMITTED
TO PERSONNEL FILES.
DATA BEING RECEIVED.
KODOS FILE--
OF ALL SURVIVORS,
THERE ARE 9
ACTUAL EYEWITNESSES
WHO CAN
IDENTIFY KODOS.
STOP.
GIVE LIST.
KIRK, J.--PRESENTLY
"ENTERPRISE" CAPTAIN,
LEIGHTON, T.,
MOULTON, E.,
RILEY, K.,
EAMES, D.--
STOP.
IS THAT STAR SERVICE
LIEUTENANT KEVIN RILEY?
AFFIRMATIVE.
RILEY, KEVIN,
PRESENTLY ASSIGNED
U.S.S. "ENTERPRISE"
COMMUNICATIONS SECTION.
STOP.
MR. SPOCK.
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT KEVIN RILEY
IN COMMUNICATIONS--
I WISH TO HAVE HIM TRANSFERRED
DOWN TO THE ENGINEERING DESK.
HE CAME UP
FROM ENGINEERING,
CAPTAIN.
WELL, I'M
SENDING HIM BACK.
ANY EXPLANATION?
HE'S A FINE
YOUNG OFFICER.
HE'S BOUND
TO CONSIDER
THIS TRANSFER
A DISCIPLINARY
ACTION.
I DON'T WISH
TO DISCUSS IT,
MR. SPOCK.
PLEASE FOLLOW
MY ORDERS.
MR. SPOCK, WHEN
THE MAN ON TOP
WALKS ALONG HIS STREET,
THE CHAIN OF COMMAND
IS OFTEN A NOOSE.
SPARE ME
YOUR PHILOSOPHICAL
METAPHORS, DOCTOR.
CAPTAIN IS
ACTING STRANGELY.
I'M ASKING
IF YOU'VE NOTICED.
NEGATIVE. YOU KNOW, THIS IS
THE FIRST TIME IN A WEEK
THAT I'VE HAD TIME
FOR A DROP OF A DREW?
WOULD YOU CARE
FOR A DRINK, MR. SPOCK?
MY FATHER'S RACE
WAS SPARED
THE DUBIOUS BENEFITS
OF ALCOHOL.
OH. NOW I KNOW
WHY THEY WERE CONQUERED.
WHAT ARE YOU SO
WORRIED ABOUT, ANYWAY?
I FIND JIM
GENERALLY KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOING.
IT WAS ILLOGICAL
FOR HIM
TO BRING THOSE
PLAYERS ABOARD.
ILLOGICAL? DID YOU
GET A LOOK
AT THAT
LITTLE JULIET?
THAT'S A PRETTY
EXCITING CREATURE.
OF COURSE, YOUR
PERSONAL CHEMISTRY
WOULD PREVENT YOU
FROM SEEING THAT.
DID IT EVER
OCCUR TO YOU
THAT HE SIMPLY
MIGHT LIKE THE GIRL?
IT OCCURRED.
I DISMISSED IT.
YOU WOULD.
DID YOU KNOW THAT HE
SUDDENLY TRANSFERRED
LIEUTENANT RILEY
TO ENGINEERING?
LOTS OF THINGS
ARE GOING AROUND HERE
THAT I DON'T KNOW,
MR. SPOCK.
NOW, HE'S THE CAPTAIN.
HE CAN TRANSFER PEOPLE
AS HE PLEASES.
YOU CAN LOOK THAT UP
IN 100 VOLUMES
OF SPACE REGULATIONS
SOMEWHERE,
ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, COME ON.
HAVE A DRINK.
NO, THANK YOU.
WELL,
YOU'RE WELCOME,
BUT I WILL,
AND PLEASE,
MR. SPOCK,
IF YOU WON'T
JOIN ME,
DON'T DISAPPROVE
OF ME,
AT LEAST NOT UNTIL
YOU'VE TRIED IT,
HUH?
[SIGH]
THIS IS THE, UH,
OBSERVATION DECK.
THAT'S THE FLIGHT
DECK DOWN THERE--
WITH
THE SHUTTLE CRAFT.
INTERESTING.
ISN'T IT?
TELL ME,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
ANYTHING.
DID YOU ORDER
THE SOFT LIGHTS
ESPECIALLY
FOR THE OCCASION?
IF I HAD ORDERED
SOFT LIGHTS,
I'D ALSO HAVE ARRANGED
FOR MUSIC AND FLOWERS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT ISN'T SO.
ON THE "ENTERPRISE,"
WE TRY TO DUPLICATE
EARTH CONDITIONS
OF NIGHT AND DAY
AS CLOSELY AS POSSIBLE.
STAR LIGHT, STAR BRIGHT.
I WISH I MAY,
I WISH I MIGHT.
DO YOU REMEMBER THAT,
CAPTAIN?
IT'S VERY OLD.
ALMOST AS OLD
AS THE STARS THEMSELVES.
AND THIS SHIP.
ALL THIS POWER
SURGING AND THROBBING,
YET UNDER CONTROL.
ARE YOU LIKE THAT, CAPTAIN?
ALL THIS POWER
AT YOUR COMMAND,
THE DECISIONS
THAT YOU HAVE TO MAKE...
COME FROM A VERY
HUMAN SOURCE.
ARE YOU, CAPTAIN?
HUMAN?
YOU CAN COUNT ON IT.
TELL ME ABOUT THE WOMEN
IN YOUR WORLD, CAPTAIN.
I'D RATHER
TALK ABOUT YOU.
YOU MUST HAVE
WANTED TO PERFORM
SINCE THE FIRST TIME
YOU SAW YOUR FATHER ACT.
WHEN WAS THAT?
IN THE BEGINNING.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT.
THAT'S NOT FAIR.
YOU HAVEN'T ANSWERED
MY QUESTION.
ABOUT THE WOMEN.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE TO KNOW?
HAS THE MACHINE
CHANGED THEM?
MADE THEM JUST PEOPLE
INSTEAD OF WOMEN?
WORLDS MAY CHANGE,
GALAXIES DISINTEGRATE,
BUT A WOMAN...
ALWAYS REMAINS A WOMAN.
ALL THIS...
AND POWER, TOO.
THE CAESAR
OF THE STARS
AND THE CLEOPATRA
TO WORSHIP HIM.
Electronic voice:
LIBRARY COMPUTER.
FULL PERSONAL DOSSIERS
ON THE FOLLOWING NAMES--
DR. THOMAS LEIGHTON,
ANTON KARIDIAN,
LIEUTENANT KEVIN RILEY.
AND CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK.
ACCOMPLISHED.
STANDING BY.
CORRELATE. CHECK
THEIR PAST HISTORIES.
REPORT ANY ITEM,
ANY PAST EPISODE
OR EXPERIENCE
THEY ALL HAVE IN COMMON.
AFFIRMATIVE.
I APPRECIATE WHATEVER
CONCERN YOU MAY HAVE
FOR THE SHIP'S
COMPANY, MR. SPOCK--
I WILL CONTINUE,
DOCTOR.
ACCORDING TO
OUR LIBRARY BANKS,
IT STARTED
ON THE EARTH COLONY
OF TARSUS IV
WHEN THE FOOD SUPPLY
WAS ATTACKED
BY AN EXOTIC FUNGUS
AND LARGELY
DESTROYED.
THERE WERE
OVER 8,000 COLONISTS
AND VIRTUALLY
NO FOOD.
AND THAT WAS WHEN
GOVERNOR KODOS
SEIZED FULL POWER
AND DECLARED
EMERGENCY
MARTIAL LAW.
I'VE HEARD OF IT.
YOU MAY NOT HAVE
HEARD IT ALL.
KODOS BEGAN
TO SEPARATE
THE COLONISTS.
SOME WOULD LIVE,
BE RATIONED WHATEVER
FOOD WAS LEFT.
THE REMAINDER
WOULD BE IMMEDIATELY
PUT TO DEATH.
APPARENTLY, HE HAD
HIS OWN THEORIES
OF EUGENICS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
HE WASN'T THE FIRST.
PERHAPS NOT,
BUT HE WAS CERTAINLY
AMONG THE MOST RUTHLESS
TO DECIDE ARBITRARILY
WHO WOULD SURVIVE
AND WHO WOULD NOT,
USING HIS OWN
PERSONAL STANDARDS
AND THEN TO IMPLEMENT
HIS DECISION
WITHOUT MERCY.
CHILDREN WATCHING
THEIR PARENTS DIE.
WHOLE FAMILIES DESTROYED.
OVER 4,000 PEOPLE.
THEY DIED QUICKLY,
WITHOUT PAIN,
BUT THEY DIED.
RELIEF ARRIVED,
BUT TOO LATE TO PREVENT
THE EXECUTIONS.
AND KODOS,
THERE NEVER WAS A POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF HIS BODY.
BUT WHAT IS
KARIDIAN TO DO
WITH IT?
HIS HISTORY BEGINS
ALMOST TO THE DAY
WHERE KODOS DISAPPEARED.
AND YOU THINK JIM
SUSPECTS HE'S KODOS?
HE'D BETTER.
THERE WERE
9 EYEWITNESSES
WHO SURVIVED
THE MASSACRE
WHO'D ACTUALLY SEEN KODOS
WITH THEIR OWN EYES.
JIM KIRK
WAS ONE OF THEM.
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF RILEY AND CAPTAIN KIRK,
EVERY OTHER EYEWITNESS
IS DEAD,
AND MY LIBRARY COMPUTER
SHOWS
THAT WHEREVER THEY WERE--
ON EARTH, ON A COLONY,
OR ABOARD SHIP--
THE KARIDIAN
COMPANY OF PLAYERS
WAS SOMEWHERE NEAR
WHEN THEY DIED.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
HEY. REC ROOM. SOMEBODY.
TALK TO ME.
LARRY MATSON
HERE.
IS THAT YOU,
RILEY?
WHAT'S UP?
NOT ME.
I AM DOWN.
IN THE ENGINEERING ROOM.
YOU'VE BEEN
A BAD BOY.
MAYBE SO.
WHATEVER I'VE DONE,
THEY'RE SURE KEEPING IT
A SECRET FROM ME.
HEY. IS THAT
UHURA PLAYING?
LET ME TALK TO HER.
I THINK
HIS HEART IS SORE.
WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU, RILEY?
A SONG.
YEP, MAKE IT
A LOVE SONG.
JUST SOMETHING
TO REASSURE ME
I'M NOT THE ONLY
LIVING THING
LEFT IN
THE UNIVERSE, HUH?
WELL, YOU'RE NOT.
I'LL PROVE IT TO YOU.
♪ THE SKIES
ARE GREEN AND GLOWING ♪
♪ WHERE MY HEART IS ♪
♪ WHERE THE SCENTED
LUNAR FLOWER'S GROWING ♪
♪ SOMEWHERE
BEYOND THE STARS ♪
♪ BEYOND ANTARES ♪
♪ I'LL BE BACK,
THOUGH IT TAKES FOREVER ♪
♪ FOREVER IS JUST A DAY ♪
♪ FOREVER IS JUST
ANOTHER JOURNEY ♪
♪ TOMORROW
A STOP ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ AND LET THE YEARS
GO FADING ♪
♪ WHERE MY HEART IS ♪
♪ WHERE MY
HEART IS ♪
♪ WHERE MY LOVE
ETERNAL IS ♪
♪ WAITING ♪
♪ SOMEWHERE ♪
♪ BEYOND THE STARS ♪
♪ BEYOND ANTARES ♪
HOW'D YOU LIKE THAT,
RILEY?
[GAGS]
[COUGHS]
HELP ME...
PLEASE.
[GLASS SHATTERS]
YOU'VE GOT TO
PULL HIM THROUGH.
I'M NOT SURE I CAN.
IF HE DIES,
THE ONLY ONE
WHO'LL BE ABLE
TO IDENTIFY KODOS
IS THE CAPTAIN,
AND HE'LL BE
THE NEXT TARGET.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 2819.1.
SHIP'S OFFICER RILEY'S
CONDITION WORSENING.
DR. McCOY MAKING LAB ANALYSIS
TO DETERMINE CAUSE AND ANTIDOTE.
ENTIRE CREW DEEPLY CONCERNED.
AS OF THIS DATE,
LAB REPORT INDICATES
PRESENCE OF
APPRECIABLE AMOUNT
OF TETRALUBISOL,
A HIGHLY
VOLATILE LUBRICANT
IN USE ABOARD SHIP.
SOMEONE TRIED
TO POISON HIM.
TETRALUBISOL IS
A MILKY SUBSTANCE.
SOMEONE COULD'VE
GOTTEN CARELESS
AND MADE A MISTAKE.
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT
AND NEITHER DO YOU.
I WANT THE CAPTAIN
TO SEE THAT REPORT.
WHEN I'VE FINISHED
LOGGING IT.
NOW.
ALL RIGHT.
[BUZZ]
COME.
MY REPORT
ON LIEUTENANT RILEY.
WILL HE MAKE IT?
HE'S GOT
A GOOD CHANCE.
AND WE PREDICT
THE SAME
FOR YOU, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK.
LET'S HAVE IT.
LIEUTENANT RILEY
WAS A WITNESS.
SO WERE YOU.
[SIGHS]
ALL RIGHT.
SOMEONE TRIED
TO KILL HIM.
COULD HAVE BEEN
AN ACCIDENT.
YOU SHOULD
BE TOLD THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN EMPIRICISM
AND STUBBORNNESS,
DOCTOR.
I CHECKED WITH
THE LIBRARY COMPUTER
JUST AS YOU DID.
I GOT THE SAME
INFORMATION.
AREN'T YOU GETTING
A LITTLE OUT OF LINE,
MR. SPOCK?
MY PERSONAL BUSINESS--
IT'S MY PERSONAL BUSINESS
WHEN IT MIGHT INTERFERE
WITH THE SMOOTH OPERATION
OF THIS SHIP.
YOU THINK
THAT HAPPENED?
IT COULD HAPPEN.
I DON'T LIKE
ANYONE MEDDLING
IN MY PRIVATE AFFAIRS,
NOT EVEN
MY SECOND IN COMMAND.
JIM, SPOCK'S
SIMPLY TRYING--
I KNOW WHAT HE'S TRYING
TO DO AND I DON'T
LIKE IT.
IT'S HIS JOB
AND YOU KNOW IT.
AND YOU ALSO KNOW...
THAT NOTHING IS PROVEN.
EVEN IN THIS CORNER
OF THE GALAXY, CAPTAIN,
TWO PLUS TWO
EQUALS 4.
ALMOST CERTAINLY AN ATTEMPT
WILL BE MADE TO KILL YOU.
WHY DO YOU
INVITE DEATH?
I'M NOT.
I'M INTERESTED
IN JUSTICE.
ARE YOU?
ARE YOU SURE
IT'S NOT VENGEANCE?
NO, I'M NOT SURE.
I WISH I WAS.
I'VE DONE THINGS
I'VE NEVER DONE BEFORE.
I'VE PLACED MY COMMAND
IN JEOPARDY.
FROM HERE ON,
I'VE GOT TO DETERMINE
WHETHER OR NOT
KARIDIAN IS KODOS.
HE IS.
YOU SOUND CERTAIN.
I WISH I COULD BE.
BEFORE I ACCUSE A MAN OF
THAT, I'VE GOT TO BE.
I SAW HIM ONCE,
20 YEARS AGO.
MEN CHANGE.
MEMORY CHANGES.
LOOK AT HIM NOW--
HE'S AN ACTOR.
HE'LL CHANGE
HIS APPEARANCE.
NO. LOGIC IS NOT ENOUGH.
I'VE GOT TO FEEL MY WAY.
MAKE ABSOLUTELY SURE.
WHAT IF YOU DECIDE
HE IS KODOS?
WHAT THEN?
DO YOU PLAY GOD,
CARRY HIS HEAD
THROUGH THE CORRIDORS
IN TRIUMPH?
THAT WON'T
BRING BACK
THE DEAD, JIM.
NO.
BUT THEY MAY
REST EASIER.
LOGIC, CAPTAIN.
DR. LEIGHTON
WAS MURDERED
WHILE
THE KARIDIAN COMPANY
WAS ON PLANET Q.
NOW AN ATTEMPT HAS
BEEN MADE AGAINST
LIEUTENANT RILEY
WHILE THE COMPANY
IS ON BOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
DOC ISN'T SURE THERE WAS
A MURDER ATTEMPT.
BESIDES,
I HAVE AN IDEA
THAT MAY PROVE--
SHH.
LISTEN.
[HUMMING ]
DO YOU HEAR IT?
THAT LOW HUM.
A PHASER.
ON OVERLOAD.
[HUMMING]
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
THERE'S A PHASER
ON OVERLOAD
IN MY QUARTERS.
IF IT BLOWS,
IT'LL TAKE OUT
THE ENTIRE DECK.
EVACUATE ALL PERSONNEL
IN THIS QUADRANT.
DOUBLE RED ALERT.
[SIREN]
YOU GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU CAN'T STAY.
GO ON. BLOCK OFF
THIS SECTION.
HURRY.
I'LL FIND IT.
EVACUATE THIS SECTION.
SEAL IT OFF.
CLEAR SECTION C4 AND C5.
[EXPLOSION]
[SIREN STOPS]
[DOOR OPENS]
WE'RE OVERDUE
FOR OUR TALK,
AREN'T WE?
I HAD HOPED
YOU WOULD HAVE RESPECTED
MY PRIVACY, CAPTAIN.
A MOMENT AGO,
WE NARROWLY AVERTED
AN EXPLOSION
WHICH WOULD HAVE
DESTROYED SEVERAL DECKS
OF THIS SHIP.
BEFORE THAT,
SOMEONE TRIED TO POISON
ONE OF MY CREWMEN.
I AM SORRY
TO HEAR THAT.
I'M SURE YOU ARE.
ARE YOU KODOS?
I ASKED YOU
A QUESTION.
DO YOU BELIEVE
THAT I AM?
I DO.
THEN I AM KODOS,
IF IT PLEASES YOU
TO BELIEVE SO.
I AM AN ACTOR.
I PLAY MANY PARTS.
YOU'RE AN ACTOR NOW.
WHAT WERE YOU
20 YEARS AGO?
YOUNGER, CAPTAIN.
MUCH YOUNGER.
SO WAS I.
BUT I REMEMBER.
LET'S SEE IF YOU DO.
READ THIS
INTO THAT COMMUNICATOR
ON THE WALL.
IT WILL BE RECORDED
AND COMPARED TO A PIECE
OF KODOS VOICE FILM
WE HAVE IN OUR FILES.
THE TEST
IS VIRTUALLY INFALLIBLE.
IT WILL TELL US WHETHER
YOU'RE KARIDIAN...
OR KODOS
THE EXECUTIONER.
READY FOR VOICE TEST.
DISGUISING YOUR VOICE
WILL MAKE NO DIFFERENCE.
"THE REVOLUTION...
"IS SUCCESSFUL,
"BUT SURVIVAL DEPENDS
ON DRASTIC MEASURES.
"YOUR CONTINUED
EXISTENCE
"REPRESENTS A THREAT
TO THE WELL-BEING
OF SOCIETY.
"YOUR LIVES
MEANS SLOW DEATH
"TO THE MORE
VALUED MEMBERS
OF THE COLONY."
THEREFORE
I HAVE NO ALTERNATIVE
BUT TO SENTENCE YOU
TO DEATH.
YOUR EXECUTION
IS SO ORDERED.
SIGNED, KODOS,
GOVERNOR OF TARSUS IV.
I REMEMBER THE WORDS.
I WROTE THEM DOWN.
YOU SAID THEM
LIKE YOU KNEW THEM.
YOU HARDLY GLANCED
AT THE PAPER.
I LEARN MY PARTS
VERY QUICKLY.
ARE YOU SURE?
ARE YOU SURE YOU DIDN'T
ACT THIS ROLE OUT
IN FRONT OF
A CAPTIVE AUDIENCE
WHOM YOU BLASTED
OUT OF EXISTENCE
WITHOUT MERCY?
I FIND YOUR USE
OF THE WORD "MERCY"
STRANGELY INAPPROPRIATE,
CAPTAIN.
HERE YOU STAND,
A PERFECT SYMBOL
OF OUR TECHNICAL SOCIETY--
MECHANIZED, ELECTRONICIZED,
AND NOT VERY HUMAN.
YOU'VE DONE AWAY
WITH HUMANITY,
THE STRIVING OF MAN
TO ACHIEVE GREATNESS
THROUGH HIS OWN
RESOURCES.
WE'VE ARMED MAN
WITH TOOLS.
THE STRIVING
FOR GREATNESS CONTINUES.
BUT KODOS--
KODOS, WHOEVER HE WAS--
OR IS.
KODOS MADE A DECISION
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
SOME HAD TO DIE
THAT OTHERS MIGHT LIVE.
YOU'RE A MAN OF DECISION,
CAPTAIN.
YOU OUGHT TO
UNDERSTAND THAT.
ALL I UNDERSTAND
IS THAT 4,000 PEOPLE
WERE NEEDLESSLY
BUTCHERED.
IN ORDER TO SAVE
4,000 OTHERS.
AND IF THE SUPPLY SHIPS
HADN'T COME EARLIER
THAN EXPECTED,
THIS KODOS OF YOURS
MIGHT HAVE GONE DOWN
IN HISTORY
AS A GREAT HERO.
BUT HE DIDN'T.
AND HISTORY
HAS MADE ITS JUDGMENT.
IF YOU'RE SO SURE
THAT I'M KODOS,
WHY NOT KILL ME NOW?
LET BLOODY VENGEANCE
TAKE ITS FINAL COURSE!
AND SEE
WHAT DIFFERENCE IT MAKES
TO THIS UNIVERSE
OF YOURS.
THOSE ARE
BEAUTIFUL WORDS,
WELL ACTED.
THEY CHANGE NOTHING.
NO, I SUPPOSE NOT.
THEY'RE MERELY TOOLS,
LIKE THIS SHIP OF YOURS.
THERE ARE NO
PREVIOUS RECORDS
TO ANTON KARIDIAN
PRIOR TO
20 YEARS AGO.
BLOOD THINS.
THE BODY FAILS.
ONE IS FINALLY GRATEFUL
FOR A FAILING MEMORY.
I NO LONGER
TREASURE LIFE,
NOT EVEN MY OWN.
I AM TIRED!
THE PAST...
IS A BLANK.
DID YOU GET
EVERYTHING YOU...
WANTED,
CAPTAIN KIRK?
IF I HAD GOTTEN...
EVERYTHING I WANTED...
YOU MIGHT NOT WALK
OUT OF THIS ROOM ALIVE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU BETTER REST...
NOW.
THERE'S
A STAIN OF CRUELTY
ON YOUR
SHINING ARMOR,
CAPTAIN.
YOU COULD HAVE
SPARED HIM...
AND ME.
YOU TALKED
OF USING TOOLS.
I WAS A TOOL,
WASN'T I?
A TOOL TO USE
AGAINST MY FATHER.
IN THE BEGINNING,
PERHAPS.
BUT LATER, I WANTED IT
TO BE MORE THAN THAT.
LATER. EVERYTHING'S
ALWAYS LATER.
LATER. LATEST.
TOO LATE.
TOO LATE, CAPTAIN.
YOU ARE
LIKE YOUR SHIP--
POWERFUL...
AND NOT HUMAN.
THERE IS NO MERCY
IN YOU.
IF HE IS KODOS,
THEN I'VE SHOWN HIM
MORE MERCY THAN
HE DESERVES.
AND IF HE ISN'T...
THEN WE'LL
LET YOU OFF
AT BENECIA,
AND NO HARM DONE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
WHO ARE YOU TO SAY
WHAT HARM WAS DONE?
WHO DO I HAVE TO BE?
MEDICAL LOG--
LIEUTENANT RILEY'S
SUFFICIENTLY RECOVERED
TO BE DISCHARGED,
BUT THE CAPTAIN
HAS ORDERED HIM
RESTRICTED TO SICK BAY
TO PREVENT
CONTACT WITH PASSENGER
WHO CALLS HIMSELF
KARIDIAN
AND WHO'S SUSPECTED
OF BEING KODOS
THE EXECUTIONER
AND OF MURDERING
THE LIEUTENANT'S FAMILY.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 2819.8.
SUSPECT UNDER SURVEILLANCE.
STRATEGIC AREAS
UNDER DOUBLE GUARD.
PERFORMANCE OF
THE KARIDIAN PLAYERS
TAKING PLACE AS SCHEDULED.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
TONIGHT, THE KARIDIAN PLAYERS
PRESENT "HAMLET,"
ANOTHER IN A SERIES
OF LIVING PLAYS
PRESENTED IN SPACE,
DEDICATED TO THE TRADITION
OF CLASSIC THEATER.
"HAMLET" IS A VIOLENT PLAY
ABOUT VIOLENT TIMES
WHEN LIFE WAS CHEAP
AND AMBITION WAS GOD.
I BELIEVE
WE HAVE A MATCH,
CAPTAIN.
BUT NOT
AN EXACT MATCH,
MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE DEALING
WITH A MAN'S LIFE.
NO MACHINE
CAN MAKE THAT DECISION.
IN THE LONG HISTORY
OF MEDICINE,
NO DOCTOR
HAS EVER CAUGHT
THE FIRST FEW MINUTES
OF A PLAY.
RILEY, DON'T
FORGET THAT--
RILEY?
CAPTAIN KIRK,
McCOY HERE.
Kirk: YES, DOCTOR.
RILEY'S GONE.
I WAS RECORDING MY LOG
ABOUT KARIDIAN AND KODOS.
IF HE OVERHEARD--
YOU'VE MADE YOUR POINT,
DOCTOR.
CAPTAIN,
SECURITY, "H" DECK--
THE WEAPONS LOCKER
HAS BEEN BROKEN INTO.
ONE PHASER IS MISSING.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
SECURITY 2 ALERT.
FIND AND RESTRAIN
LIEUTENANT KEVIN RILEY.
HE'S ARMED
AND POSSIBLY HEADED
TOWARDS THE SHIP'S THEATER.
WHITHER WILT THOU LEAD ME?
SPEAK, I'LL GO NO FURTHER.
MARK ME.
Hamlet: I WILL.
MY HOUR IS ALMOST COME,
WHEN I TO SULPHUROUS
AND TORMENTING FIRES
MUST RENDER UP MYSELF.
Hamlet: SPEAK.
I AM BOUND TO HEAR.
SO ART THOU
TO REVENGE...
WHEN THOU SHALT HEAR.
I AM THY FATHER'S
SPIRIT,
DOOMED
FOR A CERTAIN TERM
TO WALK THE NIGHT...
RILEY...
GET BACK
TO THE SICK BAY.
HE MURDERED MY FATHER...
AND MY MOTHER.
YOU COULD BE WRONG.
DON'T THROW AWAY
YOUR LIFE
ON A MISTAKE.
I'M NOT WRONG.
BUT THAT I AM FORBID
TO TELL THE SECRETS
OF MY PRISON-HOUSE...
I KNOW THAT VOICE.
THAT FACE,
I KNOW IT.
I SAW IT.
HE MURDERED THEM.
THY SOUL,
FREEZE THY YOUNG BLOOD.
IT'S AN ORDER.
GIVE ME THE WEAPON.
IF THOU DIDST EVER
THY DEAR FATHER LOVE...
GET BACK
TO THE SICK BAY.
GO ON.
[APPLAUSE]
IT'S GOING BEAUTIFULLY.
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S WRONG?
THERE WAS A VOICE
OUT OF THE PAST
HAUNTING ME,
TORTURING ME.
THERE WAS ANOTHER PART
I ONCE PLAYED LONG AGO.
I NEVER TOLD YOU
ABOUT IT.
NOW THAT SAME CURTAIN
RISES AGAIN.
THE TIME HAS COME.
NO, FATHER.
THE TIME
WILL NEVER COME.
TONIGHT,
AFTER MY PERFORMANCE,
THE LAST TWO
WHO CAN HARM YOU
WILL BE GONE.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THERE WERE 9.
NOW THERE ARE ONLY TWO,
AND THEY WILL BE GONE
AS SOON AS I.
DON'T LOOK AT ME
LIKE THAT.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
WHAT HAD TO BE DONE.
THEY HAD TO BE
SILENCED.
ALL OF THEM?
ALL 7?
MORE BLOOD
ON MY HANDS?
NO, FATHER.
NOT ANYMORE.
I'M STRONG, FATHER.
IT'S NOTHING.
Stagehand:
SECOND ACT--
3 MINUTES.
WE'LL BE READY.
DON'T YOU SEE?
ALL THE GHOSTS ARE DEAD.
I'VE BURIED THEM.
THERE'S NO MORE BLOOD
ON YOUR HANDS.
OH, MY CHILD.
MY CHILD.
YOU'VE LEFT ME
NOTHING!
YOU WERE THE ONE THING
IN MY LIFE
UNTOUCHED
BY WHAT I'D DONE.
BUT YOU'RE SAFE NOW,
FATHER.
I'VE SAVED YOU.
NOW...
NO ONE CAN TOUCH YOU.
NOT EVEN CAPTAIN KIRK.
SEE CAESAR COME.
HE'S AWED
BY YOUR GREATNESS...
YOUR SHINING
BRIGHTNESS.
BRIGHT AS A BLADE...
BEFORE IT IS
STAINED WITH BLOOD.
BRIGHT AS A BLADE.
COME WITH ME,
BOTH OF YOU.
OF COURSE.
AFTER THE PLAY.
THE PLAY IS OVER.
IT'S BEEN OVER
FOR 20 YEARS.
I WAS A SOLDIER
IN A CAUSE.
THERE WERE THINGS
TO BE DONE.
TERRIBLE THINGS.
STOP IT, FATHER!
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO JUSTIFY.
MURDER, FLIGHT,
SUICIDE, MADNESS.
I NEVER WANTED
THE BLOOD ON MY HANDS
EVER TO STAIN YOU.
I DID IT FOR YOU.
I'VE SAVED YOU.
BY KILLING
7 INNOCENT MEN.
THEY WEREN'T INNOCENT!
THEY WERE DANGEROUS!
I WOULD HAVE
KILLED A WORLD
TO SAVE HIM!
Stagehand:
CURTAIN GOING UP--
ONE MINUTE.
THE PLAY, CAPTAIN.
HE MUST GO ON.
THIS IS THE GREAT...
KARIDIAN.
GUARD.
YOU CANNOT DENY HIM
HIS LAST PERFORMANCE!
LENORE, DON'T!
AAH!
YOU'LL NEVER
GET OFF THE SHIP.
THEN IT WILL BECOME
FLOATING, TOO,
DRIFTING THROUGH SPACE
WITH THE SOUL
OF THE GREAT KARIDIAN
GIVING PERFORMANCES
AT EVERY STAR HE TOUCHES.
I KNOW HOW
TO USE THIS, CAPTAIN.
NO.
CAESAR,
BEWARE THE IDES OF MARCH.
NO, CHILD! DON'T!
UHH!
AAH!
FATHER.
O...
PROUD...
DEATH!
WHAT FEAST IS TOWARD
IN THINE ETERNAL CELL...
THAT THOU,
SUCH A PRINCE,
AT A SHOT SO BLOODILY
HAST STRUCK?
[SOBBING]
THE CURT--
THE CURTAIN.
THE CURTAIN RISES.
IT RISES.
'TIS NO TIME TO SLEEP.
THE PLAY.
THE PLAY'S THE THING...
WHEREIN WE'LL CATCH
THE CONSCIENCE OF THE KING.
MEDICAL REPORT.
[BEEP]
SHE'LL RECEIVE
THE BEST OF CARE, JIM.
SHE REMEMBERS NOTHING.
SHE EVEN THINKS
HER FATHER'S STILL ALIVE
GIVING PERFORMANCES
BEFORE CHEERING CROWDS.
YOU REALLY
CARED FOR HER,
DIDN'T YOU?
READY TO LEAVE
BENECIA ORBIT,
CAPTAIN.
STAND BY,
MR. LESLIE.
ALL CHANNELS CLEARED,
UHURA?
ALL CHANNELS CLEAR, SIR.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY,
MR. LESLIE.
LEAVING ORBIT,
SIR.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
ANSWER MY QUESTION,
ARE YOU?
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 1,
MR. LESLIE.
THAT'S AN ANSWER.