THE CEREMONY WILL BE CARRIED
ON ALL VIEWING SCREENS, SIR.
GOOD.
THERE'S A CALL FOR YOU
FROM THE BRIDGE.
KIRK HERE.
[SPOCK]
STILL NO ANSWER
FROM EARTH OUTPOST
NUMBER 2, CAPTAIN,
AND NOW NUMBER 3
HAS GONE SILENT.
MAINTAIN COURSE
TO OUTPOST 4.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
KIRK OUT.
SINCE THE DAYS
OF THE FIRST
WOODEN VESSELS,
ALL SHIPMASTERS
HAVE HAD ONE
HAPPY PRIVILEGE--
THAT OF UNITING
TWO PEOPLE
IN THE BONDS
OF MATRIMONY,
AND SO WE ARE
GATHERED HERE TODAY
WITH YOU,
ANGELA MARTINE,
AND YOU,
ROBERT TOMLINSON,
IN THE SIGHT
OF YOUR FELLOWS
IN ACCORDANCE
WITH OUR LAWS
AND OUR MANY
BELIEFS--
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
ALERT! ALERT!
ALL DECKS--ALERT!
CAPTAIN TO THE BRIDGE.
KIRK HERE.
[SPOCK]
EARTH OUTPOST 4 REPORTS
THEY'RE UNDER ATTACK--
A SPACE VESSEL,
IDENTITY UNKNOWN.
FULL AHEAD. ALL DECKS--
CONDITION RED.
ALL DECKS--
ALL DECKS--CONDITION RED.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 1709.2.
PATROLLING OUTPOSTS
GUARDING THE NEUTRAL ZONE
BETWEEN PLANETS
ROMULUS AND REMUS
AND THE REST OF THE GALAXY,
RECEIVED EMERGENCY CALL
FROM OUTPOST 4.
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
IS MOVING TO INVESTIGATE
AND ASSIST.
OUTPOST 4 REPORTED
UNDER ATTACK, SIR,
THEN MESSAGE TERMINATES.
VERIFIED, CAPTAIN.
OUR SPEED IS NOW
MAXIMUM, SIR.
POSITION--8 MINUTES
FROM OUTPOST 4
AT THIS VELOCITY, SIR.
SCOTTY...
I'VE ALREADY TALKED
TO MY ENGINE ROOM, SIR.
WE'LL GET MORE SPEED
OUT OF HER.
DID OUTPOST 4
GIVE ANYTHING AT ALL
ON THE ATTACKING
VESSEL, LIEUTENANT?
NO IDENTIFICATION,
SIR.
THERE CAN'T BE MUCH DOUBT
WHO'S ATTACKING, SIR.
MR. SPOCK,
PUT THIS STAR SECTOR
ON OUR SCREEN.
NOW SHOW
OUR POSITION.
SIGNAL THIS TO
ALL DECKS, LIEUTENANT.
ALL DECKS
STANDING BY, SIR.
THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
IN OUR NEXT ACTION,
WE CAN RISK NEITHER
MISCALCULATION NOR ERROR
BY ANY MAN ABOARD.
LISTEN CAREFULLY.
SCIENCE OFFICER.
REFERRING TO THE MAP
ON YOUR SCREENS,
YOU WILL NOTE BEYOND
THE MOVING POSITION
OF OUR VESSEL
A LINE OF EARTH
OUTPOST STATIONS.
CONSTRUCTED ON ASTEROIDS,
THEY MONITOR
THE NEUTRAL ZONE
ESTABLISHED BY TREATY
AFTER THE EARTH-ROMULAN
CONFLICT
OF OVER A CENTURY AGO.
AS YOU MAY RECALL
FROM YOUR HISTORIES,
THIS CONFLICT WAS FOUGHT,
BY OUR STANDARDS TODAY,
WITH PRIMITIVE
ATOMIC WEAPONS
AND IN PRIMITIVE
SPACE VESSELS
WHICH ALLOWED
NO QUARTER,
NO CAPTIVES,
NOR WAS THERE
EVEN SHIP-TO-SHIP
VISUAL COMMUNICATION.
THEREFORE, NO HUMAN,
ROMULAN, OR ALLY
HAS EVER SEEN THE OTHER.
EARTH BELIEVES
THE ROMULANS TO BE WARLIKE,
CRUEL, TREACHEROUS,
AND ONLY
THE ROMULANS KNOW
WHAT THEY THINK
OF EARTH.
THE TREATY,
SET BY SUB-SPACE RADIO,
ESTABLISHED
THIS NEUTRAL ZONE,
ENTRY INTO WHICH
BY EITHER SIDE
WOULD CONSTITUTE
AN ACT OF WAR.
THE TREATY HAS BEEN
UNBROKEN SINCE THAT TIME.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT YOU DO NOT KNOW
AND MUST NOW BE TOLD
IS THAT MY COMMAND ORDERS
ON THIS SUBJECT
ARE PRECISE AND INVIOLABLE.
NO ACT, NO PROVOCATION
WILL BE CONSIDERED
SUFFICIENT REASON
TO VIOLATE THE ZONE.
WE MAY DEFEND OURSELVES,
BUT, IF NECESSARY
TO AVOID INTERSPACE WAR,
BOTH THESE OUTPOSTS
AND THIS VESSEL
WILL BE CONSIDERED
EXPENDABLE.
CAPTAIN OUT.
WE KNOW OUTPOST 4
HAS BEEN ATTACKED, SIR,
SO IF WE INTERCEPT
ROMULANS NOW--
AFTER A WHOLE CENTURY,
WHAT WILL A ROMULAN SHIP
LOOK LIKE, MR. STILES?
I DOUBT IF THEY'LL RADIO
AND IDENTIFY THEMSELVES.
YOU'LL KNOW, SIR.
THEY'RE PAINTED LIKE
A GIANT BIRD OF PREY.
I HAD NO IDEA THAT HISTORY
WAS YOUR SPECIALTY.
FAMILY HISTORY.
THERE WAS A CAPTAIN STILES
IN THE SPACE SERVICE THEN,
TWO COMMANDERS,
SEVERAL JUNIOR OFFICERS--
ALL LOST
IN THAT WAR, SIR.
THEIR WAR,
MR. STILES.
NOT YOURS.
DON'T FORGET IT.
YES, SIR.
OUTPOST 2 COMING
INTO SENSOR RANGE, CAPTAIN.
OUTPOST 2 WAS THE
FIRST TO GO SILENT,
LIEUTENANT?
YES, CAPTAIN.
THEN OUTPOST 3
AN HOUR LATER.
SWEEPING THE AREA
OF OUTPOST 2.
SENSOR READING
INDEFINITE.
DOUBLE-CHECKING
OUTPOST 3.
I READ DUST AND DEBRIS.
BOTH EARTH OUTPOSTS GONE
AND THE ASTEROIDS
THEY WERE CONSTRUCTED ON...
PULVERIZED.
OPEN A CHANNEL TO OUR
NEAREST COMMAND BASE.
QUARTER-HOUR REPORTS
ON OUR POSITION
AND STATUS.
YES, SIR.
CALL BATTLE STATIONS,
MR. SULU.
BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL HANDS
TO BATTLE STATIONS.
BATTLE STATIONS.
BATTLE STATIONS. ALL
DECKS ACKNOWLEDGE.
ALL DECKS
ACKNOWLEDGE, SIR.
ALL STATIONS
SHOW GREEN.
ENERGIZE MAIN PHASERS,
MR. STILES.
ALL WEAPONS TO FULL POWER.
ALL WEAPONS
TO FULL POWER.
PHASER CONTROL ROOM.
ENERGIZE.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
PHASER CONTROL
ACKNOWLEDGING.
ALL WEAPONS
ENERGIZING TO FULL.
HAPPY WEDDING DAY...
ALMOST.
YOU WON'T GET OFF
MY HOOK THIS EASILY.
I'M GOING TO
MARRY YOU, MISTER,
BATTLE OR PHASER WEAPONS
NOTWITHSTANDING.
WELL, MEANWHILE,
TEMPORARILY AT LEAST,
I AM STILL
YOUR SUPERIOR OFFICER.
SO GET WITH IT, MISTER.
HELM WEAPONS
SHOW READY.
STARBOARD AND MIDSHIP WEAPONS
ACKNOWLEDGED.
ALL WEAPONS BATTERIES READY.
OUTPOST 4 NOW
5 MINUTES AWAY, SIR.
AND IT'S SHOWING
ON MY SENSORS,
CAPTAIN.
AT LEAST IT'S
STILL THERE.
SIR, REGAINING CONTACT
WITH OUTPOST 4.
SWITCHING
TO SPEAKERS.
OUT...OUTPOST 4.
DO YOU READ ME, ENTERPRISE?
THIS IS COMMANDER HANSEN.
KIRK HERE. WE'RE
MINUTES AWAY, HANSEN.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
OUTPOSTS 2, 3, AND 8
ARE GONE.
UNKNOWN WEAPON.
COMPLETELY DESTROYED,
EVEN THOUGH
WE WERE ALERTED.
HAD OUR DEFLECTOR SHIELD
ON MAXIMUM.
HIT BY ENORMOUS POWER.
FIRST ATTACK
BLEW OUR DEFLECTOR SHIELD.
IF THEY HIT US AGAIN
WITH OUR DEFLECTOR
SHIELD GONE...
DO YOU READ ME, ENTERPRISE?
CONFIRM WHAT
HIT YOU, HANSEN.
WHAT VESSEL?
IDENTITY?
SPACE VESSEL,
ONLY GLIMPSE OF.
CAN YOU LOCATE
THE INTRUDER FOR US?
NEGATIVE.
IT SEEMS TO HAVE
DISAPPEARED SOMEHOW.
I HAVE YOU ON MY SCREEN NOW.
SWITCHING TO VISUAL.
TIE US IN.
TIED IN, SIR.
ENTERPRISE, CAN YOU SEE IT?
MY COMMAND POST HERE.
WE'RE A MILE DEEP
ON AN ASTEROID.
ALMOST SOLID IRON.
AND EVEN
THROUGH OUR DEFLECTORS,
IT DID THIS.
CAN YOU SEE?
AFFIRMATIVE.
YOUR VISUAL.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
ON THE INTRUDER?
NO IDENTIFICATION.
NO ANSWER TO OUR CHALLENGE.
ONLY A GLIMPSE OF IT.
THEN THEY FIRED
SOMETHING AT US--
SOME FORM
OF HIGH-ENERGY PLASMA.
FANTASTIC POWER.
THEN THE WHOLE VESSEL
DISAPPEARED,
BUT IT'S OUT THERE SOMEWHERE.
OUR SENSORS
SHOW THAT MUCH.
ENTERPRISE, SOMETHING
COMING ON OUR VIEWING SCREEN--
COMING AT US FAST.
LOCK US ON
TO YOUR SCREEN.
SWITCHING.
CAN YOU SEE IT,
ENTERPRISE?
CAN YOU SEE HER?
IT'S BECOMING VISIBLE
IN THE CENTER
OF MY SCREEN.
DO YOU HAVE
PHASER CAPACITY?
WE'RE STILL
OUT OF RANGE.
NEGATIVE. PHASERS GONE.
WEAPONS CREW DEAD.
MAKE CHALLENGE.
WARN THAT SHIP OFF.
I'M TRYING TO, SIR.
THEY DON'T ACKNOWLEDGE.
OUTPOST 4...
DISINTEGRATED,
CAPTAIN.
POSITION
OF THE INTRUDER,
MR. SPOCK.
DISAPPEARED.
INTERESTING HOW THEY BECAME
VISIBLE FOR JUST A MOMENT.
WHEN THEY OPENED FIRE.
PERHAPS NECESSARY WHEN
THEY USE THEIR WEAPONS.
I HAVE A BLIP ON
THE MOTION SENSOR, CAPTAIN.
COULD BE THE INTRUDER.
GO TO FULL MAGNIFICATION.
SCREEN IS ON
FULL MAG, SIR.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
INVISIBILITY IS
THEORETICALLY POSSIBLE,
CAPTAIN--
SELECTIVE BENDING
OF LIGHT--
BUT THE POWER COST
IS ENORMOUS.
THEY MAY HAVE SOLVED
THAT PROBLEM.
CONTINUING TO CHALLENGE, SIR.
STILL NO RESPONSE.
DISCONTINUE.
CONTACT REMAINING
OUTPOSTS.
HAVE THEM SIGNAL US
ANY SIGHTINGS
OR SENSOR READINGS
IN THEIR AREA.
BLIP HAS CHANGED
ITS HEADING, CAPTAIN.
AND IN A VERY
LEISURELY MANEUVER.
THEY MAY NOT BE
AWARE OF US.
THEIR INVISIBILITY SCREEN
MAY WORK BOTH WAYS.
WITH THAT KIND
OF POWER CONSUMPTION,
THEY MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO SEE US.
HIS HEADING
IS NOW 111...
MARK 14--
THE EXACT HEADING
A ROMULAN VESSEL
WOULD TAKE, JIM,
TOWARD THE NEUTRAL ZONE...
AND HOME.
PARALLEL COURSE.
DON'T YOU MEAN
INTERCEPTION COURSE, SIR?
NEGATIVE.
YOU AND MR. SULU
WILL MATCH COURSE
AND SPEED
WITH THE OBJECT ON
OUR SENSORS EXACTLY,
MOVE FOR MOVE.
IF HE HAS SENSORS,
I WANT HIM TO
THINK THAT WE'RE
A REFLECTION,
AN ECHO.
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
ARE YOU TO CROSS
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
WITHOUT
MY DIRECT ORDERS.
ACKNOWLEDGED, SIR.
CANCEL
BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL DECKS--
STANDBY ALERT.
CANCEL
BATTLE STATIONS, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
MAY I RESPECTFULLY
REMIND THE CAPTAIN
WHAT HAS HAPPENED?
THE ROMULANS HAVE CROSSED
THE NEUTRAL ZONE,
ATTACKED OUR OUTPOSTS,
KILLED OUR MEN.
MR. STILES--
ADD TO THAT THE FACT THAT
IT WAS A SNEAK ATTACK.
MR. STILES, ARE YOU
QUESTIONING MY ORDERS?
NEGATIVE, SIR.
I'M POINTING OUT
THAT WE COULD
HAVE ROMULAN SPIES
ABOARD THIS SHIP.
I AGREE, SIR.
RESPECTFULLY
RECOMMEND
ALL DECKS MAINTAIN
SECURITY ALERT.
VERY WELL.
ALL DECKS--
SECURITY ALERT.
SECURITY ALERT, SIR.
PICKING UP
COMMUNICATIONS, SIR.
IT'S FROM THEIR SHIP.
PIPE IT IN.
SOUNDS LIKE CODE, SIR.
I HAVE A FIX ON IT,
CAPTAIN.
I BELIEVE
I CAN LOCK ON IT,
GET A PICTURE
OF THEIR BRIDGE.
PUT IT
ON THE SCREEN.
DECODING?
CRYPTOGRAPHY
IS WORKING ON IT, SIR.
GIVE IT TO SPOCK.
I DIDN'T QUITE
GET THAT, MR. STILES.
NOTHING, SIR.
REPEAT IT.
I WAS SUGGESTING
THAT MR. SPOCK
COULD PROBABLY
TRANSLATE IT
FOR YOU, SIR.
I ASSUME YOU'RE
COMPLIMENTING MR. SPOCK
ON HIS ABILITY TO DECODE.
I'M NOT SURE, SIR.
WELL, HERE'S ONE THING
YOU CAN BE SURE OF, MISTER--
LEAVE ANY BIGOTRY
IN YOUR QUARTERS.
THERE'S NO ROOM
FOR IT ON THE BRIDGE.
DO I MAKE
MYSELF CLEAR?
YOU DO, SIR.
TRANSMISSION
HAS BEEN CUT OFF.
I MADE A TAPE
OF IT, SIR.
VERY WELL.
[TRANSMISSION PLAYING]
SOMETHING VISUAL AHEAD,
CAPTAIN,
AT EXTREME RANGE.
HE'S CHANGING
COURSE, SIR.
STAY WITH HIM,
HELM.
TURNING, SIR.
WE GROW VISIBLE.
ATTEND THE CLOAKING SYSTEM.
IT CONSUMES MUCH POWER,
COMMANDER, WITH NO ENEMY
TO CONCERN US.
THAT EARTH OUTPOST
CALLED TO AN EARTH VESSEL.
NOW IT FOLLOWS US.
WHICH NEITHER RETREATS
NOR GROWS NEAR, WHICH
TURNS AS WE TURN.
COMMANDER, IT IS
OUR JUDGMENT WE RUN
FROM A REFLECTION.
PERHAPS SO,
BUT MY JUDGMENT PREVAILS.
CLOAKING SYSTEM
ON, SIR.
IT IS GOOD WE APPROACH
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
NOT TOO SOON FOR ME
TO SEE THE STARS OF HOME.
I KNOW THEY ARE
FOLLOWING.
IF AN EARTH SHIP,
WHY DOES HE
NOT ATTACK?
FIRST STUDY THE ENEMY,
SEEK WEAKNESS.
IF I WERE
THEIR COMMANDER,
THAT IS WHAT
I WOULD DO.
MY COMMANDER
SENT FOR DECIUS.
A MESSAGE WAS DISPATCHED.
YOU'VE BROKEN
THE RULE OF SILENCE.
ONLY IN CODE, COMMANDER,
TO INFORM OUR PRAETOR
OF THIS GLORIOUS MISSION.
YOUR CARELESSNESS
MIGHT HAVE ENDED
THIS GLORIOUS MISSION.
YOU'RE REDUCED
TWO STEPS IN RANK.
RETURN TO POST.
TAKE CARE,
COMMANDER.
HE HAS FRIENDS,
AND FRIENDS OF
HIS KIND MEAN POWER,
AND POWER IS DANGER.
DANGER AND I
ARE OLD COMPANIONS.
WE'VE SEEN A HUNDRED
CAMPAIGNS TOGETHER,
AND STILL I DO NOT
UNDERSTAND YOU.
I THINK YOU DO.
NO NEED TO TELL YOU
WHAT HAPPENS
THE MOMENT
WE REACH HOME WITH PROOF
OF THE EARTHMEN'S WEAKNESS,
AND WE WILL HAVE PROOF.
THE EARTH COMMANDER
WILL FOLLOW. HE MUST.
AND WHEN HE ATTACKS,
WE WILL DESTROY HIM.
OUR GIFT TO THE HOMELAND--
ANOTHER WAR.
IF WE ARE THE STRONG,
IS THIS NOT
THE SIGNAL FOR WAR?
MUST IT ALWAYS BE SO?
HOW MANY COMRADES
HAVE WE LOST IN THIS WAY?
OUR PORTION,
COMMANDER...
IS OBEDIENCE.
OBEDIENCE...
DUTY.
DEATH AND MORE DEATH.
SOON EVEN ENOUGH
FOR THE PRAETOR'S TASTE.
CENTURION...
I FIND MYSELF
WISHING FOR DESTRUCTION
BEFORE WE CAN RETURN.
WORRY NOT.
LIKE YOU, I AM
TOO WELL-TRAINED IN MY DUTY
TO PERMIT IT.
CONTINUE
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
NOW BACK
TO THE FIRST COURSE.
THEY'RE TURNING, SIR.
WE'RE STAYING
WITH THEM.
STEADY ON 111 MARK 14.
BACK ON THEIR ORIGINAL
COURSE, CAPTAIN,
TOWARD THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
WHAT'S OUR POSITION,
NAVIGATOR?
WE'LL ENTER THE NEUTRAL ZONE
IN LESS THAN AN HOUR, SIR,
ASSUMING, OF COURSE,
THAT WE DON'T TURN BACK.
[SCOTT]
WE NOW HAVE ABOARD
DEBRIS FROM OUTPOST 4,
CAPTAIN.
BRING IT
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
ARE YOU READY,
GENTLEMEN?
FROM THE OUTPOST
PROTECTIVE SHIELD--
CAST RODINIUM.
THIS IS THE HARDEST
SUBSTANCE
KNOWN TO OUR SCIENCE.
LAB THEORIZES
AN ENVELOPING
ENERGY PLASMA
FORCING
AN IMPLOSION.
COMMENTS?
OBVIOUSLY, THEIR WEAPONRY
IS SUPERIOR TO OURS,
AND THEY HAVE A PRACTICAL
INVISIBILITY SCREEN.
YOU'RE DISCUSSING
TACTICS.
DO YOU REALIZE WHAT
THIS REALLY COMES DOWN TO?
MILLIONS AND MILLIONS
OF LIVES HANGING ON WHAT
THIS VESSEL DOES NEXT.
OR ON WHAT
THIS VESSEL FAILS
TO DO, DOCTOR.
YES. WELL, GENTLEMEN,
THE QUESTION STILL REMAINS.
CAN WE ENGAGE THEM WITH
A REASONABLE POSSIBILITY
OF VICTORY?
NO QUESTION.
THEIR POWER IS
SIMPLE IMPULSE.
MEANING WE CAN OUTRUN THEM?
TO BE USED
IN CHASING THEM
OR RETREATING...SIR?
GO AHEAD, MR. STILES.
I CALLED THIS SESSION
FOR OPINIONS.
WE HAVE TO ATTACK
IMMEDIATELY.
EXPLAIN.
THEY'RE STILL ON OUR SIDE
OF THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THERE WOULD BE NO DOUBT
THAT THEY BROKE THE TREATY.
ATTACK WITHOUT
A VISIBLE TARGET?
HOW DO WE
AIM OUR PHASERS?
AIM WITH SENSORS.
NOT ACCURATE, BUT IF
WE BLANKET THEM--
HOPE FOR
A LUCKY SHOT BEFORE
THEY ZERO IN ON US?
AND IF WE DON'T?
ONCE BACK,
THEY'LL REPORT WE SAW
THEIR WEAPONS AND RAN.
AND IF THEY COULD REPORT
THAT THEY DESTROYED US?
THESE ARE ROMULANS!
YOU RUN AWAY FROM THEM,
AND YOU GUARANTEE WAR.
THEY'LL BE BACK--
NOT JUST ONE SHIP,
BUT WITH EVERYTHING
THEY'VE GOT.
YOU KNOW THAT,
MR. SCIENCE OFFICER.
YOU'RE THE EXPERT IN THESE
PEOPLE, BUT YOU'VE ALWAYS
LEFT OUT THAT ONE POINT.
WHY? I'M VERY
INTERESTED IN WHY.
SIT DOWN, MISTER.
I AGREE.
ATTACK.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
WE FIGHT TO PREVENT
A FIGHT?
BASED ON WHAT?
MEMORIES OF A WAR
OVER A CENTURY AGO?
ON THEORIES ABOUT
A PEOPLE WE'VE NEVER
EVEN MET FACE TO FACE?
WE KNOW WHAT
THEY LOOK LIKE.
YES. INDEED WE DO,
MR. STILES.
AND IF THE ROMULANS
ARE AN OFFSHOOT
OF MY VULCAN BLOOD--
AND I THINK THIS
LIKELY--
THEN ATTACK BECOMES
EVEN MORE IMPERATIVE.
WAR IS NEVER
IMPERATIVE, MR. SPOCK.
IT IS FOR THEM, DOCTOR.
VULCAN, LIKE EARTH,
HAD ITS AGGRESSIVE
COLONIZING PERIOD,
SAVAGE EVEN
BY EARTH STANDARDS.
IF THE ROMULANS RETAIN
THIS MARTIAL PHILOSOPHY,
THEN WEAKNESS
IS SOMETHING
WE DARE NOT SHOW.
DO YOU WANT
A GALACTIC WAR
ON YOUR CONSCIENCE?
CAPTAIN TO BRIDGE.
THIS IS UHURA,
CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S OUR POSITION?
COURSE UNCHANGED, SIR.
ESTIMATING TREATY BOUNDARY
IN 21 MINUTES.
ARE YOU CONTINUING
TO BROADCAST
TACTICAL REPORTS?
AFFIRMATIVE, CAPTAIN.
AND AT THIS DISTANCE?
APPROXIMATELY THREE HOURS
BEFORE RECEIVING A REPLY
TO OUR FIRST MESSAGE.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
CHECK OUR COURSE AHEAD,
MR. SPOCK.
A COMET,
MAGNITUDE 7,
DEAD AHEAD,
AND THE INTRUDER
CHANGING COURSE
TOWARD IT.
COMET ICARUS-4.
COMPOSITION?
QUITE ORDINARY.
AN IONIZED MASS,
A TRAIL OF FROZEN
VAPOR PARTICLES.
AND WHEN AN OBJECT
PASSES THROUGH IT,
EVEN AN INVISIBLE OBJECT...
IT LEAVES
A VISIBLE TRAIL.
AH!
OUR CHANCE, GENTLEMEN.
PREPARE TO ATTACK.
ALL HANDS--BATTLE STATIONS.
[ALERT BLARING]
I HOPE WE WON'T
NEED YOUR SERVICES,
BONES.
AMEN TO THAT.
YOU'RE TAKING
A BIG GAMBLE, JIM.
BATTLE STATUS?
ALL STATIONS MANNED,
CAPTAIN.
PHASER WEAPONS
ENERGIZED.
SET FOR
PROXIMITY BLAST.
INTRUDER NOW BEARING DIRECTLY
FOR COMET'S TAIL.
PLOT HIS EXACT POINT
OF ENTRY, MR. STILES.
COMPUTED.
ON THE BOARD, SIR.
THE MOMENT HE BEGINS
ENTERING THE COMET'S TAIL,
HE BECOMES VISIBLE.
END RUN, GENTLEMEN.
WE'LL SWING AROUND
THE OTHER SIDE
AND CATCH HIM
AT THAT MOMENT.
ACKNOWLEDGED,
CAPTAIN.
HE'S MAINTAINING
THAT BEARING, CAPTAIN.
LET'S GET HIM,
MR. SULU.
HOW PLEASING
TO THE EYE IT IS.
BEHOLD A MARVEL
IN THE DARKNESS.
YOU SPOKE
OF ENTRAPMENT.
ITS MANY PARTICLES
WILL OBSCURE
THEIR SENSING DEVICE,
CENTURION.
WE ENTER IT,
COMMANDER.
ONCE FULLY OBSCURED,
WE WILL TURN SUDDENLY BACK
UPON OUR ADVERSARY.
AT LAST THE SCREEN
IS CLEAR, COMMANDER.
CLEAR?
OUR REFLECTION NO
LONGER FOLLOWS US.
ESCAPE MANEUVER ONE!
QUICKLY!
WE'RE LOSING SENSOR
CONTACT, CAPTAIN.
STEADY AS SHE GOES.
PHASER CREWS READY?
PHASER CREWS
SIGNAL READY, SIR.
HE'LL ONLY
BE VISIBLE
FOR A MOMENT.
STAND BY.
SIR...
[SPOCK]
AT THE LAST MOMENT,
HE MUST HAVE--
GUESSED OUR MOVE.
HARD ASTARBOARD,
HELM!
HARD ASTARBOARD.
HE DID EXACTLY
WHAT I WOULD HAVE DONE.
I WON'T
UNDERESTIMATE HIM AGAIN.
NOW, FIRE BLIND.
LAY DOWN A PATTERN.
TRAVERSE PATTERN.
ALL PHASERS FIRE!
PHASER ONE, FIRE.
PHASER TWO, FIRE!
PHASER TWO, FIRE.
DIVERT ALL POWER
TO WEAPONS.
PHASER OVERLOAD.
CONTROL CIRCUIT
BURNOUT.
IT'LL TAKE TIME
TO CORRECT, SIR.
CAPTAIN, ARE THEY
SURRENDERING?
FULL ASTERN!
EMERGENCY WARP SPEED!
DO WE HAVE
EMERGENCY WARP?
FULL POWER, SIR.
IT'S STILL
OVERTAKING US.
IF WE CAN GET
ONE PHASER
WORKING, SIR,
ONE SHOT WOULD
DETONATE IT.
NAVIGATION?
ESTIMATE IT'LL OVERTAKE US
IN TWO MINUTES, SIR.
PHASERS, MR. SPOCK?
IMPOSSIBLE, CAPTAIN.
FEED THIS
TO THE SPACE RECORDER
AND JETTISON IMMEDIATELY.
CAPTAIN, SHOULD
I CONTINUE LOG ENTRY--
YEOMAN...
AFFIRMATIVE.
CONTINUE LOG ENTRIES.
YES, SIR.
10 SECONDS
TO IMPACT.
CAPTAIN...
IT'S DISSIPATING,
SIR.
[STILES]
IT MUST HAVE
A RANGE LIMIT.
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
IMPACT!
LIMITED RANGE.
PHASERS OPERATIONAL,
CAPTAIN.
INTRUDER BEARING
111 MARK 14.
BACK TO
HIS OLD COURSE.
HE MAY THINK WE'RE
DESTROYED, CAPTAIN.
I WOULDN'T MAKE
THAT ASSUMPTION.
I DON'T THINK THEIR CAPTAIN
WILL, EITHER.
INTRUDER HOLDING STEADY,
COURSE 111 MARK 14.
SAME AS BEFORE,
MR. SULU.
STAY WITH HIM.
COMMANDER,
THE REFLECTION RETURNS.
ACTIVATE OUR CLOAK.
COMMANDER,
OUR FUEL RUNS LOW.
QUICKLY!
THE EARTH VESSEL?
IMPOSSIBLE.
IT MOVES AS WE MOVE.
ITS COMMANDER IS NOT ONE
TO REPEAT A MISTAKE.
WE'LL ENTER THE NEUTRAL ZONE
IN ONE MINUTE, CAPTAIN.
DO WE VIOLATE
THE TREATY, CAPTAIN?
THEY DID, DOCTOR.
ONCE INSIDE, THEY
CAN CLAIM WE DID.
A SETUP.
THEY WANT WAR,
WE FURNISH
THE PROVOCATION.
WE'RE STILL ON
OUR SIDE, CAPTAIN.
LET'S GET THEM
WHILE WE ARE--
BEFORE WE ENTER
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
FULL AHEAD, MR. SULU.
MAXIMUM WARP.
AHEAD, SIR.
MAXIMUM.
PHASERS, STAND BY.
SIR, AT THIS DISTANCE?
WE KNOW
THEIR ACHILLES HEEL,
MR. STILES.
THEIR WEAPON TAKES
ALL THEIR ENERGY.
THEY MUST BECOME VISIBLE
IN ORDER TO LAUNCH IT.
A PHASER HIT
AT THIS DISTANCE
WOULD BE THE WILDEST
STROKE OF LUCK.
I'M AWARE OF THAT,
MR. STILES.
ARE PHASERS READY?
PHASERS SHOW READY, SIR.
COMMANDER!
EVASIVE ACTION.
THE EARTH SHIP AGAIN.
20 SECONDS
TO NEUTRAL ZONE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
INFORM COMMAND BASE...
IN MY OPINION,
NO OPTION.
ON MY RESPONSIBILITY,
WE ARE PROCEEDING
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
STEADY AS WE GO, MR. SULU.
CONTINUE FIRING.
COMMANDER, THEY STAY
WITHIN RANGE!
I WILL TEND
TO THE CENTURION.
NO NEED.
CENTURION IS DEAD.
WHY DON'T WE FIRE,
COMMANDER?
NO.
NO, HE'S SHREWD,
THIS STARSHIP COMMANDER.
HE TRIES TO MAKE US
WASTE ENERGY.
HE HAS ESTIMATED
WE HAVE ONLY ENOUGH...
IT IS TIME.
ALL DEBRIS INTO
DISPOSAL TUBES.
YES, COMMANDER.
THE BODY
OF THE CENTURION, TOO.
FORGIVE ME,
MY OLD FRIEND,
BUT I MUST USE
ALL MY EXPERIENCE NOW
TO GET HOME.
MOTION SENSOR
SIGNAL STOPPED.
CEASE FIRE.
DEBRIS SCATTER
AHEAD, SIR.
WE'VE HIT HIM.
MR. SPOCK?
VESSEL WRECKAGE--
METAL MOLDS, CONDUIT,
PLASTAFORM,
AND A BODY, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER...
HOWEVER?
INSUFFICIENT MASS, SIR.
WHAT?
SIMPLE DEBRIS.
NOT A VESSEL,
A TRICK.
GO TO SENSOR PROBES.
NOTHING, SIR.
NO MOTION
OUT THERE AT ALL.
WE'VE LOST THEM,
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 1709.6.
WE ARE AT THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
HAVE LOST CONTACT
WITH THE INTRUDER.
NO REACTION
ON OUR MOTION SENSORS,
BUT BELIEVE THE ROMULAN VESSEL
TO BE SOMEWHERE CLOSE BY
WITH ALL ENGINES AND SYSTEMS
SHUT DOWN.
THE ENTERPRISE IS ALSO PLAYING
THE SILENT WAITING GAME
IN HOPE OF REGAINING CONTACT.
CAPTAIN, I MUST MAKE
FURTHER REPAIRS
ON THE TRANSFER COIL.
IT'S GIVING OUT AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
WORK QUIETLY.
[SOFTLY]
NOW 20 FULL CYCLES,
COMMANDER.
STILL NO SIGN.
I SAY HE'S BEEN FOOLED.
HE MUST HAVE GONE ON.
SHH!
HE IS THERE,
SOMEWHERE.
I FEEL IT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
NOW MOTIONLESS
FOR 9 HOURS, 47 MINUTES.
CAN I GET YOU SOMETHING
FROM THE GALLEY, SIR?
COFFEE, AT LEAST?
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
BRING IT TO THE BRIDGE.
I'LL BE THERE IN A MOMENT.
YES, SIR.
I WISH I WERE ON
A LONG SEA VOYAGE SOMEWHERE.
NOT TOO MUCH DECK TENNIS,
NO FRANTIC DANCING,
AND NO RESPONSIBILITY.
WHY ME?
I LOOK AROUND
THAT BRIDGE,
AND I SEE THE MEN WAITING
FOR ME TO MAKE THE NEXT MOVE.
AND, BONES...
WHAT IF I'M WRONG?
CAPTAIN--
NO, I DON'T REALLY
EXPECT AN ANSWER.
BUT I'VE GOT ONE.
SOMETHING
I SELDOM SAY TO A...
CUSTOMER, JIM.
IN THIS GALAXY,
THERE'S A MATHEMATICAL
PROBABILITY
OF 3 MILLION
EARTH-TYPE PLANETS...
AND IN ALL
THE UNIVERSE,
3 MILLION MILLION
GALAXIES LIKE THIS.
AND IN ALL OF THAT,
AND PERHAPS MORE,
ONLY ONE OF EACH OF US.
DON'T DESTROY
THE ONE NAMED KIRK.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
WHAT--
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
A SIGNAL,
COMMANDER.
WE HAVE HIM.
MOVE TOWARD HIM.
POWER ON.
REVERSE COURSE.
HE'LL TRY TO SLIP
UNDER US.
LATERAL POWER, SIR.
COMING AROUND, SIR.
PHASERS, FIRE.
HOW, COMMANDER? HOW?
HE'S A SORCERER,
THAT ONE.
HE READS THE THOUGHTS
IN MY BRAIN.
OUR FUEL SUPPLY
ALL BUT GONE,
AND HE STAYS
OUT OF REACH.
WE ARE BEATEN.
CAN IT BE TRUE?
THE PRAETOR'S
FINEST AND PROUDEST
FLAGSHIP BEATEN!
PERHAPS WE CAN
YET SAVE
YOUR PRAETOR'S PRIDE
FOR HIM.
MORE DEBRIS
INTO THE TUBES!
DECIUS, DO WE HAVE
SOME OF THE OLD-STYLE
NUCLEAR WARHEADS ABOARD?
YES, COMMANDER, BUT ONLY
FOR SELF-DESTRUCTION.
PLACE ONE IN
WITH THE DEBRIS.
PROXIMITY FUSE.
YES, COMMANDER,
AT ONCE.
MORE WRECKAGE,
SIR, SCATTERING
ACROSS OUR PATH.
CEASE FIRE.
DEBRIS ON OUR SCANNERS.
ANALYSIS, QUICKLY.
SAME TYPE
AS BEFORE, SIR,
EXCEPT...
ONE METAL-CASED OBJECT.
HELM, HARD OVER!
PHASERS, FIRE POINT-BLANK!
PHASERS, FIRE!
GLORIOUS.
GLORIOUS!
NOW WE GO HOME.
THEY'RE AT OUR MERCY.
COMMANDER...
I REMIND YOU
OF YOUR DUTY.
CAPTAIN TO SICK BAY.
McCOY HERE.
CASUALTIES?
22, SO FAR.
MAINLY RADIATION BURNS,
MOSTLY FROM THE SHIP'S
OUTER AREAS.
COULD HAVE BEEN MUCH,
MUCH WORSE, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
REPORT, MR. SPOCK?
NUCLEAR DEVICE
OF SOME KIND, SIR.
OUR PHASERS DETONATED IT
LESS THAN 100 METERS AWAY.
SHIP DAMAGE?
MAINLY OVERLOADS
AND CIRCUIT BURNOUTS.
WEAPONS STATUS?
WE'VE ONLY THE FORWARD
PHASER ROOM.
FULLY OPERABLE, SCOTTY?
YES, SIR,
BUT SPECIALIST TOMLINSON
IS MANNING IT ALONE.
NO STANDBY CREW
AVAILABLE.
SIR, MY FIRST ASSIGNMENT
WAS IN WEAPONS CONTROL.
GO.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TAKE OVER NAVIGATION.
YES, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE ENGINE POWER
NOW, CAPTAIN,
IF YOU'D LIKE TO MOVE OFF
AND MAKE REPAIRS.
NO, NO.
MAYBE WE CAN
PULL THEM BACK
TO OUR SIDE
OF THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
HOLD OUR POSITION.
PLAY DEAD.
STILL NO SIGN
OF MOVEMENT, COMMANDER.
WE HAVE DAMAGED
OURSELVES.
OUR FUEL RESERVE
IS GONE.
AND IT IS OUR DUTY
TO CRUSH
THE PRAETOR'S
ENEMIES.
I DO NOT TRUST
THEIR CAPTAIN.
WE ARE IN
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THEY WILL NOT ENTER.
IF YOU REFUSE,
PERMIT ME THE GLORY
OF THE KILL, COMMANDER.
WE WILL ATTACK...
BUT ON MY ORDER.
DAMAGE REPORTS,
MR. STILES?
NEGATIVE.
WILL YOU REQUIRE
ANY ASSISTANCE HERE?
THIS TIME,
WE'LL HANDLE THINGS
WITHOUT YOUR HELP, VULCAN.
TOMLINSON!
ENEMY VESSEL
BECOMING VISIBLE, SIR.
FORWARD PHASERS, STAND BY.
FIRE!
STILES, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
STILES!
WEAPONS!
MR. SULU,
PREPARE TO MOVE IN
ON THE ROMULAN VESSEL.
SHIP-TO-SHIP,
UHURA.
PUT THIS
ON THE SCREEN.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
OPEN, SIR.
CAPTAIN...
STANDING BY TO BEAM
YOUR SURVIVORS ABOARD OUR SHIP.
PREPARE TO ABANDON
YOUR VESSEL.
NO.
NO. IT IS NOT OUR WAY.
I REGRET THAT WE MEET
IN THIS WAY.
YOU AND I ARE OF A KIND.
IN A DIFFERENT REALITY,
I COULD HAVE
CALLED YOU FRIEND.
WHAT PURPOSE WILL IT
SERVE TO DIE?
WE ARE CREATURES OF DUTY,
CAPTAIN.
I HAVE LIVED MY LIFE BY IT.
JUST ONE MORE DUTY
TO PERFORM.
YOU ALL RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK?
YES, VERY WELL.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
AND YOU, MR. STILES?
I'M ALIVE, SIR,
BUT I WOULDN'T BE.
MR. SPOCK, HE PULLED ME OUT
OF THE PHASER ROOM.
HE SAVED MY LIFE.
HE RISKED HIS LIFE,
AND AFTER I--
I SAVED
A TRAINED NAVIGATOR
SO THAT HE COULD
RETURN TO DUTY.
I AM CAPABLE OF NO OTHER
FEELINGS IN SUCH MATTERS.
HOW MANY MEN
DID WE LOSE, BONES?
ONLY ONE...
TOMLINSON,
THE BOY WHO WAS
GOING TO GET MARRIED
THIS MORNING.
HIS FIANCEE'S
AT THE CHAPEL NOW.
WE FINALLY RECEIVED
AN ANSWER FROM
COMMAND BASE, SIR.
THEY SAY THEY'LL SUPPORT
WHATEVER DECISION
YOU HAVE TO MAKE.
IT NEVER MAKES
ANY SENSE.
YOU BOTH HAVE TO KNOW
THAT THERE WAS A REASON.
I'M ALL RIGHT.