ANYTHING
FROM THE LANDING PARTY?
THEY SHOULD BE SENDING UP
A REPORT MOMENTARILY,
CAPTAIN.
OHH.
SOMETHING WRONG?
A KINK IN MY BACK.
THAT'S IT.
A LITTLE HIGHER,
PLEASE.
PUSH. PUSH HARD.
DIG IT IN THERE,
MR. SP--
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
THAT'S SUFFICIENT.
YOU NEED SLEEP,
CAPTAIN.
IF IT'S NOT
OUT OF LINE--
I HAVE ENOUGH OF THAT
FROM DR. McCOY, YEOMAN.
THANK YOU.
DR. McCOY IS CORRECT,
CAPTAIN.
AFTER WHAT THIS SHIP
HAS BEEN THROUGH
IN THE LAST 3 MONTHS,
THERE'S NOT A CREWMAN ABOARD
WHO'S NOT IN NEED OF A REST.
MYSELF EXCEPTED,
OF COURSE.
HAVE DR. McCOY'S
REPORT
CHANNELED TO
MY QUARTERS,
LIEUTENANT.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
BEAUTIFUL,
BEAUTIFUL.
NO ANIMALS.
NO PEOPLE.
NO WORRIES.
JUST WHAT
THE DOCTOR
ORDERED,
RIGHT, DOCTOR?
I COULDN'T HAVE
PRESCRIBED BETTER.
WE ARE
ONE WEARY SHIP.
YOU THINK THE CAPTAIN
WILL AUTHORIZE
A SHORE LEAVE HERE?
WELL,
DEPENDING UPON MY REPORT
AND THAT OF THE OTHER
SCOUTING PARTIES.
YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE
TO SEE THIS PLACE
TO BELIEVE IT.
IT'S LIKE SOMETHING OUT OF
ALICE IN WONDERLAND.
THE CAPTAIN
HAS TO COME DOWN.
HE'D LIKE IT.
HE NEEDS IT.
YOU'VE GOT YOUR PROBLEMS.
I'VE GOT MINE.
BUT HE'S GOT OURS, PLUS HIS,
PLUS 430 OTHER PEOPLE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
TO GET SOME
CELL-STRUCTURE
RECORDS.
A BLADE OF GRASS,
A BUSH, A TREE,
A FLOWER PETAL.
WITH THESE, WE CAN
TELL THE WHOLE
PLANET BIOLOGY.
OH, MY PAWS
AND WHISKERS!
I'LL BE LATE.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
HAVE YOU SEEN
A RATHER LARGE
WHITE RABBIT
WITH A YELLOW WAISTCOAT
AND WHITE GLOVES
HEREABOUT?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SULU!
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DID YOU SEE THEM?
SEE WHAT?
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING.
WHAT IS IT, DOC?
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk:
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3025...
UH, .3.
WE ARE ORBITING
AN UNINHABITED PLANET
IN THE OMICRON-DELTA
REGION,
A PLANET
REMARKABLY LIKE EARTH
OR HOW WE REMEMBER
EARTH TO BE--
PARKLIKE,
BEAUTIFUL, GREEN,
FLOWERS, TREES,
GREEN LAWN,
QUIET AND RESTFUL,
ALMOST TOO GOOD
TO BE TRUE.
SIR, I DON'T SEE
YOUR NAME
IN ANY OF
THE SHORE PARTIES.
WELL, I MAY BE TIRED,
YEOMAN,
BUT I'M NOT
FALLING APART.
DISMISSED.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
Man: SHORE-LEAVE PARTY ONE,
STAND BY YOUR SECTION.
YOU WILL BE CALLED
IN ALPHABETICAL ORDER.
MR. SPOCK, WE'RE BEAMING DOWN
THE STARBOARD SECTION FIRST.
WHICH SECTION WOULD YOU
LIKE TO GO WITH?
NOT NECESSARY
IN MY CASE, CAPTAIN.
ON MY PLANET,
"TO REST"
IS TO REST,
TO CEASE
USING ENERGY.
TO ME, IT IS
QUITE ILLOGICAL
TO RUN UP AND DOWN
ON GREEN GRASS
USING ENERGY
INSTEAD
OF SAVING IT.
[INTERCOM
WHISTLES]
KIRK HERE.
Uhura: DR. McCOY CALLING
FROM THE PLANET, CAPTAIN.
YES.
OPEN A CHANNEL, UHURA.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU BEAMING DOWN?
I HADN'T PLANNED TO,
BONES. WHY?
WELL, EITHER
OUR SCOUTING PROBES
AND DETECTORS
ARE MALFUNCTIONING
AND ALL US SCOUTS CARELESS
AND BEAUTY-INTOXICATED,
OR I MUST REPORT MYSELF
UNFIT FOR DUTY.
EXPLAIN.
ON THIS SUPPOSEDLY
UNINHABITED PLANET,
I JUST SAW
A LARGE RABBIT
PULL A GOLD WATCH
FROM HIS VEST
AND CLAIM
THAT HE WAS LATE.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD BONES.
ALL RIGHT,
I GOT ONE FOR YOU.
THE RABBIT WAS FOLLOWED
BY A LITTLE BLOND GIRL,
RIGHT?
AS A MATTER
OF FACT, YES,
AND THEY DISAPPEARED
THROUGH A HOLE
IN A HEDGE.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR,
I'LL TAKE YOUR REPORT
UNDER CONSIDERATION.
CAPTAIN OUT.
THAT'S A McCOY PILL
WITH A LITTLE MYSTERY
SUGARCOATING.
HE WANTS TO GET ME
DOWN THERE.
AFRAID I WON'T
SWALLOW IT.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
SOMETHING I DID
COME TO DISCUSS.
YES, MR. SPOCK,
WHAT IS IT?
I PICKED THIS UP
FROM DR. McCOY'S LOG.
WE HAVE
A CREW MEMBER ABOARD
WHO'S SHOWING SIGNS
OF STRESS AND FATIGUE--
REACTION TIME
DOWN 9-12%,
ASSOCIATIONAL READING
NORM MINUS 3.
THAT'S MUCH TOO LOW
A RATING.
HE'S BECOMING IRRITABLE
AND QUARRELSOME,
YET HE REFUSES TO TAKE
REST AND REHABILITATION.
HE HAS THAT RIGHT,
BUT WE'VE FOUND--
A CREWMAN'S RIGHT ENDS
WHERE THE SAFETY
OF THE SHIP BEGINS.
NOW, THAT MAN WILL GO
ASHORE ON MY ORDERS.
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
"JAMES KIRK."
ENJOY YOURSELF, CAPTAIN.
IT'S AN INTERESTING PLANET.
I BELIEVE YOU'LL FIND IT
QUITE PLEASANT,
VERY MUCH LIKE
YOUR EARTH.
SCOUTS HAVE DETECTED
NO ANIMALS, ARTIFACTS,
OR FORCE FIELDS
OF ANY KIND,
ONLY PEACE, SUNSHINE,
AND GOOD AIR.
YOU'LL HAVE NO PROBLEMS.
ALWAYS HAVE TO
BE WORK WITH YOU?
SO MUCH LOVELINESS.
YOU WON'T FIND
ALL THIS SO LOVELY
IF OUR REPORT
FOR THE CAPTAIN
ISN'T READY
WHEN HE ASKS FOR IT.
OHH.
WHICH SHOULDN'T
BE LONG.
RODRIGUEZ, TELLER,
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
WE'VE COMPLETED
THE SPECIMEN SURVEY.
GOOD. THAT SHOULD BE
SUFFICIENT.
BEAM IT UP TO MR. SPOCK
WHEN YOU'RE READY,
AND START
ENJOYING YOURSELVES.
THANK YOU, SIR.
AND SIR,
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
DR. McCOY AND
MR. SULU THAT WAY.
THANK YOU.
RESTFUL.
AFTER WHAT
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH,
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
A PLACE
THIS BEAUTIFUL EXISTS.
IT IS BEAUTIFUL.
SO LOVELY,
AND RESTFUL.
I MEAN, AFFIRMATIVE,
CAPTAIN.
McCOY!
[ECHOS]
OVER HERE.
BONES, KNOW ANY GOOD
RABBIT JOKES LATELY?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I DO,
BUT THIS IS NOT
ONE OF THEM.
LOOK AT THIS.
I SAW WHAT I SAW,
OR MAYBE
I HALLUCINATED IT.
BUT I WANT YOU
TO TAKE A LOOK AT IT
AND TELL ME
WHAT YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
FOOTPRINTS.
COULD BE A RABBIT.
IT WOULD HAVE TO BE
AN UNUSUAL CREATURE
TO MAKE
THIS SIZE TRACKS.
WHAT ABOUT MR. SULU?
WILL HE CONFIRM
WHAT YOU SAW?
NEGATIVE. HE WAS
EXAMINING THE FLORA
AT THE TIME.
[BEEPS]
BRIDGE,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WHERE IS MR. SULU?
COLLECTING SPECIMENS.
Uhura:
BRIDGE.
HAS THE FIRST SHORE PARTY
BEAMED DOWN YET?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE JUST
ABOUT TO START.
GET THIS MESSAGE
TO ALL SHORE PARTIES--
STAND BY. NO ONE
IS TO LEAVE THE SHIP.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
YOU MEAN
YOU'RE CANCELING
THE SHORE LEAVE
ON ACCOUNT OF THIS,
JIM?
YOU'RE THE DOCTOR,
DOCTOR. CAN YOU
EXPLAIN THIS?
WELL, NO, BUT...
NEITHER CAN I.
I ADMIT
IT LOOKS HARMLESS.
PROBABLY
IS HARMLESS,
BUT BEFORE I BRING
MY PEOPLE DOWN HERE,
I WANT PROOF
IT'S HARMLESS.
[GUNSHOT]
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
TARGET SHOOTING, CAPTAIN.
ISN'T IT A BEAUTY?
I HAVEN'T GOT
ANYTHING LIKE THIS
IN MY COLLECTION.
WHERE DID YOU GET IT,
MR. SULU?
I FOUND IT.
I KNOW IT'S
A CRAZY COINCIDENCE,
BUT I'VE ALWAYS
WANTED ONE
LIKE THIS.
FOUND IT LYING
RIGHT OVER THERE--
AN OLD-TIME
POLICE SPECIAL,
AND IN BEAUTIFUL
CONDITION.
HASN'T BEEN ONE
LIKE THIS MADE
IN, OH,
A COUPLE CENTURIES.
MR. SULU.
IT FIRES
LEAD PELLETS
PROPELLED BY
EXPANDING GASES
FROM A CHEMICAL
EXPLOSION.
I'LL HANG ON TO IT.
THE FRESH AIR SEEMS
TO HAVE MADE YOU
TRIGGER HAPPY.
DR. McCOY'S RABBIT, SIR,
HE MUST HAVE GONE
THROUGH HERE.
ARE YOU SURE
OUR INSTRUMENTS
DIDN'T SHOW
ANY ANIMAL LIFE
ON THIS PLANET?
ABSOLUTELY.
NO BIRDS, NO MAMMALS,
NO INSECTS--NOTHING.
I'M CERTAIN OUR READINGS
WEREN'T OFF.
I'D LIKE TO BELIEVE THIS
IS AN ELABORATE GAG, BUT...
YEOMAN BARROWS,
YOU ACCOMPANY MR. SULU.
FIND OUT WHERE
THOSE TRACKS CAME FROM.
DOCTOR,
YOU COME WITH ME
BACK TO THE GLADE.
I'D LIKE TO TAKE
ANOTHER LOOK
AT THAT AREA.
THIS IS TURNING OUT TO BE
ONE VERY UNUSUAL
SHORE LEAVE.
WELL, IT COULD HAVE
BEEN WORSE.
HOW?
YOU COULD HAVE
SEEN THE RABBIT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
BONES? YOU GETTING
A PERSECUTION COMPLEX?
WELL, YEAH,
I'M BEGINNING
TO FEEL
A LITTLE BIT
PICKED ON, IF THAT'S
WHAT YOU MEAN.
WELL,
I KNOW THE FEELING
VERY WELL.
I HAD IT
AT THE ACADEMY.
AN UPPERCLASSMAN THERE--
ONE PRACTICAL JOKE
AFTER ANOTHER
AND ALWAYS ON ME--
MY OWN PERSONAL DEVIL,
A GUY BY THE NAME
OF FINNEGAN.
AND YOU BEING
THE VERY SERIOUS YOUNG--
SERIOUS?
I'LL MAKE A CONFESSION,
BONES.
I WAS ABSOLUTELY GRIM,
WHICH DELIGHTED
FINNEGAN NO END.
HE'S THE KIND OF GUY
TO PUT A BOWL OF COLD SOUP
IN YOUR BED
OR A BUCKET OF WATER
PROPPED ON A HALF-OPEN DOOR.
YOU NEVER KNEW
WHERE HE'D STRIKE NEXT.
MORE TRACKS.
LOOKS LIKE YOUR RABBIT
CAME FROM OVER THERE.
A GIRL'S FOOTPRINTS.
THE YOUNG BLOND GIRL
I SAW CHASING HIM.
YES.
YOU FOLLOW THE RABBIT.
I'LL BACKTRACK THE GIRL.
I'LL MEET YOU AROUND
THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE HILL.
GOOD.
I GOT A PERSONAL GRUDGE
AGAINST THAT RABBIT, JIM.
JIM.
FINNEGAN?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN
I'M GOING TO STRIKE,
HUH, JIM?
HA HA HA HA!
HOW'S THIS?
COME ON, COME ON.
IT'S ME, FINNEGAN.
ALL RIGHT,
JIMMY BOY.
HA HA HA HA!
WHOO-HA HA HA HA!
GO AHEAD,
LAY ONE ON ME.
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
YOU ALWAYS WANTED,
ISN'T IT?
[LAUGHS]
COME ON. COME ON.
[LAUGHING]
ALL RIGHT, LET'S TRY
THAT ONE AGAIN.
COME ON.
Barrows:
AAH!
GO!
ANY EXCUSE,
JIM, BABY.
RUN AWAY!
AAH!
[SCREAMS]
WHAT? WHAT?
YEOMAN BARROWS.
[BARROWS WHIMPERS
AND CRIES]
WHAT HAPPENED?
I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, I DO KNOW,
I GUESS.
I WAS FOLLOWING
THE TRACKS,
AND THERE HE WAS.
WHO WAS?
HIM. [SOBS]
BARROWS,
GIVE ME YOUR REPORT.
HE--
HE HAD A CLOAK, SIR,
AND--AND A DAGGER
WITH JEWELS ON IT.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU'RE NOT IMAGINING
ALL THIS?
CAPTAIN, I KNOW
IT SOUNDS INCREDIBLE,
BUT I DID NOT
IMAGINE IT
ANY MORE THAN I IMAGINED
HE DID THIS.
SOUNDS LIKE
DON JUAN.
YES.
IT WAS--
IT WAS SO...
SORT OF STORYBOOK
WALKING AROUND HERE,
AND I WAS THINKING,
"ALL A GIRL NEEDS IS...
DON JUAN."
JUST DAYDREAMING
THE WAY YOU WOULD
ABOUT SOMEONE
YOU'D LIKE TO MEET.
MR. SULU WAS WITH YOU.
WHERE IS HE NOW?
HE RAN AFTER HIM.
STAY WITH HER, DOCTOR.
MR. SULU!
SULU!
MR. SULU?
RUTH?
RUTH.
JIM, DARLING,
IT IS ME.
IT IS RUTH.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3025.8.
INVESTIGATION OF THIS
INCREASINGLY UNUSUAL
PLANET CONTINUES,
AND WE
ARE SEEING THINGS
THAT CANNOT
POSSIBLY EXIST,
YET THEY ARE
UNDENIABLY REAL.
[BEEPS]
McCOY, DO YOU READ ME?
RUTH...
RUTH,
HOW CAN IT BE YOU?
HOW COULD YOU...
POSSIBLY BE HERE?
YOU HAVEN'T AGED.
IT'S BEEN 15 YEARS.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
NONE OF THAT
MATTERS.
[BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
McCoy: DID YOU FIND
MR. SULU, CAPTAIN?
WHAT?
DID YOU FIND
MR. SULU?
NO,
BUT I'M SURE
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
SIR?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, I'M FINE.
[BEEPS]
RODRIGUEZ
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
YES, MR. RODRIGUEZ.
CAPTAIN,
A WHILE AGO,
I SAW--
WELL, BIRDS,
A WHOLE FLOCK
OF THEM.
DON'T YOU LIKE BIRDS,
MR. RODRIGUEZ?
I LIKE THEM FINE,
SIR,
BUT ALL OUR SURVEYS
SHOWED--
THEN, OFFHAND,
I'D SAY OUR INSTRUMENTS
ARE DEFECTIVE.
THERE ARE INDEED
LIFE FORMS
ON THIS PLANET.
SIR, UH...
OUR SURVEYS
COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
THAT WRONG.
MR. RODRIGUEZ,
HAVE THE SEARCH PARTIES
RENDEZVOUS AT THE GLADE.
I'D LIKE SOME ANSWERS
TO ALL THIS.
AYE AYE, SIR.
YOU HAVE TO GO?
I DON'T WANT TO.
YOU'LL SEE ME AGAIN
IF YOU WANT TO.
YOU HAVEN'T
TOLD ME...
DO WHAT YOU
HAVE TO DO...
AND I'LL BE WAITING.
RUTH.
[BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
Spock:
CAPTAIN.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
GETTING STRANGE READINGS
FROM THE PLANET'S
SURFACE, CAPTAIN.
SOME SORT OF
POWER FIELD
DOWN THERE.
SPECIFY.
HIGHLY SOPHISTICATED
TYPE OF ENERGY
DRAINING OUR POWER
AND INCREASING.
BEGINNING TO AFFECT
OUR COMMUNICATIONS.
CAN YOU PINPOINT
THE SOURCE?
COULD BE COMING FROM
BENEATH THE PLANET'S
SURFACE.
PATTERNS WOULD INDICATE
SOME SORT OF
INDUSTRIAL ACTIVITY.
KEEP ME POSTED,
MR. SPOCK.
WE'LL CONTINUE
OUR INVESTIGATION
DOWN HERE.
CAPTAIN OUT.
Dr. McCoy:
FEELING BETTER?
Barrows:
A LITTLE,
BUT I WOULDN'T WANT
TO BE ALONE HERE.
WHY NOT?
THIS IS A BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
A LITTLE STRANGE,
I'LL ADMIT.
THAT'S JUST IT.
IT'S ALMOST
TOO BEAUTIFUL.
I WAS THINKING,
EVEN BEFORE
MY TUNIC WAS TORN,
THAT IN A PLACE
LIKE THIS,
A GIRL SHOULD BE...
OH, LET'S SEE NOW,
A GIRL SHOULD BE DRESSED
LIKE A FAIRY-TALE PRINCESS
WITH LOTS
OF FLOATY STUFF
AND A TALL HAT
WITH A VEIL.
I SEE WHAT YOU MEAN,
BUT THEN YOU'D HAVE
WHOLE ARMIES
OF DON JUANS
TO FIGHT OFF...
AND ME, TOO.
IS THAT A PROMISE,
DOCTOR?
OH, DOCTOR,
THEY'RE LOVELY.
LOOK AT ME, DOCTOR--
A LADY TO BE PROTECTED
AND FOUGHT FOR.
A PRINCESS
OF THE BLOOD ROYALE.
YOU ARE ALL
OF THOSE THINGS...
AND MANY MORE.
THEY'LL LOOK EVEN LOVELIER
WITH YOU WEARING THEM.
DOCTOR...
I'M AFRAID.
NOW, LOOK,
I DON'T KNOW
HOW OR WHY,
BUT THE DRESS IS HERE.
I'D LIKE
TO SEE YOU IN IT.
WHY DON'T YOU
PUT IT ON?
ALL RIGHT...
BUT YOU STAY
RIGHT THERE.
AND DON'T PEEK.
MY DEAR GIRL,
I AM A DOCTOR.
WHEN I PEEK,
IT'S IN THE LINE
OF DUTY.
[BEEPS]
Rodriguez:
CALLING DR. McCOY.
McCOY HERE.
I, UH...
I CAN'T READ YOU
VERY WELL.
IS THIS RODRIGUEZ?
THIS IS ALL THE VOLUME
I CAN GET ON THIS THING.
I CAN'T READ YOU WELL,
EITHER.
CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
RENDEZVOUS AT THAT GLADE
WHERE HE FIRST FOUND YOU.
RIGHT.
WHAT THE DEVIL'S
WRONG WITH...
COMMUNICATIONS?
ESTEBAN.
[ROARS]
[WHISPERS]
Doctor.
Doctor!
Doctor McCoy!
[SNARLS]
Kirk: YOU'RE THE SCIENCE
OFFICER, MR. SPOCK.
I WANT SOME ANSWERS.
FIRST THERE WAS McCOY'S
ALICE IN WONDERLAND
WHERE THERE WAS SUPPOSEDLY
NO ANIMAL LIFE.
AND SULU'S GUN
WHERE THERE WAS NO
REFINED METAL DETECTED.
RODRIGUEZ' BIRDS...
AND THEN MY...
WELL,
THE 2 PEOPLE I SAW.
ANY CHANCE
THESE COULD BE
HALLUCINATIONS?
ONE HALLUCINATION
FLATTENED ME WITH
A CLOUT ON THE JAW.
THE OTHER...
THAT SOUNDS LIKE
A PAINFUL REALITY.
YES.
THERE MUST BE
SOME LOGICAL
EXPLANATION.
YOUR SIGNAL IS
VERY WEAK.
CAN YOU TURN UP
YOUR GAIN?
I'M ALREADY
ON MAXIMUM.
CAPTAIN,
SHALL I BEAM DOWN
AN ARMED PARTY?
NEGATIVE. OUR PEOPLE HERE
ARE ARMED WITH PHASERS.
BESIDES,
THERE'S YET TO BE
ANY REAL DANGER.
CAPTAIN OUT.
McCOY.
McCOY, DO YOU READ ME?
KIRK TO McCOY.
COME IN.
CAPTAIN, TAKE COVER!
THERE'S A SAMURAI
AFTER ME.
A WHAT?
I MEAN,
THERE WAS...
CAPTAIN,
YOU'VE GOT TO BELIEVE ME.
I DO. I'VE MET
SOME INTERESTING
PERSONALITIES MYSELF.
HAVE YOU SEEN
ANY OF THE OTHERS
FROM THE LANDING PARTY?
GOT A CALL
A FEW MINUTES AGO
FROM RODRIGUEZ.
SAID YOU WERE
RENDEZVOUSING
BACK AT THE GLADE.
I HOPE
HE GOT THROUGH
TO EVERYBODY.
COMMUNICATIONS
ARE ALMOST OUT.
THAT'S NOT ALL.
SO'S MY PHASER.
YEAH.
WE BETTER GET
BACK TO THE GLADE.
YES, SIR.
LOOK.
SOMEONE BEAMING DOWN
FROM THE BRIDGE.
TRYING TO.
SOMETHING'S
OBSTRUCTING IT.
MR. SPOCK.
MY ORDERS WERE
NO ONE WAS TO LEAVE
THE SHIP.
NECESSARY, CAPTAIN.
UNABLE TO CONTACT YOU
BY COMMUNICATOR,
AND THE TRANSPORTER
IS USELESS TO US NOW.
AS I TOLD YOU BEFORE,
THERE'S AN UNUSUAL
POWER FIELD DOWN HERE.
IT'S SOAKING UP
ALL THE ENERGY
AT THE SOURCE.
I CALCULATED
THE RATE OF ITS GROWTH
AND REASONED THAT
I JUST MIGHT BE ABLE TO
TRANSPORT ONE MORE PERSON.
GOOD. WE CAN
USE YOUR HELP.
WE'RE STRANDED
DOWN HERE, CAPTAIN?
UNTIL WE DISCOVER
WHAT THIS IS
ALL ABOUT.
THERE'S NO ONE HERE.
THIS IS WHERE
THE CAPTAIN SAID
TO RENDEZVOUS.
I'D SWEAR I HEARD SOMEONE
MOVING AROUND.
DON'T TALK
LIKE THAT.
A PRINCESS
SHOULDN'T BE AFRAID,
NOT WITH A BRAVE KNIGHT
TO PROTECT HER.
[TIGER ROARS]
THAT WAY.
SPREAD OUT.
LET'S FIND IT.
[HOOFBEATS]
THESE THINGS
CANNOT BE REAL.
HALLUCINATIONS
CAN'T HARM US.
GO BACK
TO WHERE YOU WERE.
OH!
[SCREAMS]
THAT DOESN'T WORK.
HE'S DEAD.
[CRYING]
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
ALL CONTACT
WITH THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN LOST.
WE'RE TRAPPED HERE.
OUR SHIP'S SURGEON,
MY PERSONAL FRIEND,
IS DEAD.
WE'RE CERTAIN NOW
THAT WHATEVER
WE'RE FACING
IS TERRIBLY REAL.
IT'S MY FAULT.
IT NEVER
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED.
IT'S MY FAULT.
IT IS, IT IS.
I'M TO BLAME.
YEOMAN.
WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
I NEED EVERY CREWMAN
ALERT AND THINKING.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN!
YOU'D BETTER HAVE
A LOOK AT THIS, SIR.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NEITHER DO I,
MR. SULU,
BUT BEFORE WE LEAVE
THIS PLANET, I WILL.
IT'S LIKE A DUMMY,
CAPTAIN.
IT COULDN'T
BE ALIVE.
TRICORDER?
STILL OPERATING,
SIR.
MR. SPOCK.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF THAT?
THIS IS NOT
HUMAN SKIN TISSUE,
CAPTAIN.
IT MORE CLOSELY
RESEMBLES
THE CELLULAR CASTING
WE USE FOR
WOUND REPAIRS--
MUCH FINER,
OF COURSE.
I WANT
AN EXACT JUDGMENT,
MR. SPOCK.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
A MECHANICAL
CONTRIVANCE.
IT HAS THE SAME
BASIC CELL STRUCTURE
AS THE PLANTS HERE.
EVEN THE TREES,
THE GRASS.
ARE YOU SAYING
THIS IS A PLANT,
MR. SPOCK?
I'M SAYING
THAT THESE ARE ALL
MULTICELLULAR CASTINGS.
THE PLANTS, THE ANIMALS,
THE PEOPLE--
THEY'RE ALL BEING
MANUFACTURED.
BY WHO?
AND WHY?
AND WHY
THESE PARTICULAR THINGS?
ALL WE KNOW
FOR CERTAIN
IS THAT THEY ACT
EXACTLY LIKE
THE REAL THING,
JUST AS PLEASANT...
OR JUST AS DEADLY.
[AIRPLANE APPROACHES]
WHAT IS IT?
OF ALL
THE CRAZY THINGS...
REMEMBER WHAT
I WAS TELLING YOU
A LITTLE WHILE AGO,
ABOUT THE EARLY WARS
AND THE FUNNY AIR
VEHICLES THEY USED?
THAT'S ONE OF THEM.
CAN IT HURT US?
NOT UNLESS IT MAKES
A STRAFING RUN.
A WHAT?
THE WAY THEY USED
TO ATTACK PEOPLE
ON THE GROUND.
COME ON.
ANGELA...
CAPTAIN!
McCOY'S BODY.
HE'S GONE.
HE'S BEEN DRAGGED OFF.
THE BLACK KNIGHT, TOO.
SPOCK?
AT THIS POINT, CAPTAIN,
MY ANALYSIS MAY NOT
SOUND VERY SCIENTIFIC.
McCOY'S DEATH
IS A SCIENTIFIC FACT.
THERE IS ONE
SLIGHT POSSIBILITY,
VERY SLIM,
BUT NEVERTHELESS--
CAPTAIN,
WHAT WERE YOUR THOUGHTS
JUST BEFORE
YOU ENCOUNTERED
THE PEOPLE
YOU DESCRIBED?
I WAS...
I WAS THINKING
ABOUT THE ACADEMY.
MY DAYS...
Finnegan:
HEY, JIM BABY!
I SEE YOU BROUGHT OUT
REINFORCEMENTS.
HA! WELL, I'M WAITING
FOR YOU, JIMMY BOY.
FINNEGAN.
FINNEGAN!
WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
TO MY PEOPLE?
WHOO, HA HA HA HA...
TAKE SULU.
FIND McCOY'S BODY.
THIS MAN
IS MY PROBLEM.
CAPTAIN, WAIT.
THAT'S AN ORDER,
MR. SPOCK.
HERE I AM!
HA HA HA! RUN!
♪ JIM ♪
HA HA! HA HA HA!
HA HA HA!
HEY, JIM...
CAN'T YOU SEE ME?
HA HA HA!
COME AND GET ME! HA HA!
HERE I AM!
YOU'RE BLIND!
YOU NEVER COULD
FIND YOUR HEAD
WITH BOTH HANDS!
LIKE IT USED TO BE,
JIMMY.
REMEMBER?
HA HA HA HA!
HEY, JIM...
I WANT SOME ANSWERS.
AH. COMING UP.
GET UP.
GET UP!
ALWAYS FIGHT FAIR,
DON'T YOU?
YOU OFFICER
AND GENTLEMAN, YOU.
YOU'RE A STUPID
UNDERCLASSMAN.
I'VE GOT THE EDGE.
I'M STILL
20 YEARS OLD.
LOOK AT YOU.
HEH.
YOU'RE AN OLD MAN.
[SCREAMS]
AAH...
I--I CAN'T MOVE
ME LEG.
I CAN'T FEEL ME LEG.
MY BACK IS BROKEN.
YOU'VE BROKEN
ME BACK.
FEEL THAT?
CAN YOU
FEEL THAT, NOW?
SLEEP SWEET,
JIMMY BOY.
SLEEP AS LONG
AS YOU LIKE.
SLEEP FOREVER,
JIM BABY.
FOREVER AND FOREVER.
HA HA HA HA...
HA HA. WON'T YOU
EVER LEARN, JIM BOY?
YOU NEVER COULD TAKE ME,
YOU KNOW.
FINNEGAN...
ONE THING.
SURE.
NAME IT.
ANSWERS.
EARN THEM!
NOT BAD.
KIND OF MAKES UP
FOR THINGS,
HUH, JIM?
A LOT OF THINGS.
WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING
TO MY PEOPLE?
I NEVER ANSWER QUESTIONS
FROM PLEBES, JIMMY BOY.
I'M NOT A PLEBE.
THIS IS TODAY,
15 YEARS LATER.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I'M BEING EXACTLY
WHAT YOU EXPECT ME
TO BE, JIMMY BOY.
DID YOU ENJOY IT,
CAPTAIN?
YES, I ENJOYED IT.
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS...
I DID ENJOY IT.
THE ONE THING I WANTED TO DO
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS WAS
BEAT THE TAR
OUT OF FINNEGAN.
WHICH SUPPORTS A THEORY
I'VE BEEN FORMULATING.
THAT WE'RE ALL MEETING
PEOPLE AND THINGS
THAT WE HAPPEN
TO BE THINKING ABOUT
AT THE MOMENT.
YES. SOMEHOW,
OUR THOUGHTS ARE READ,
THESE THINGS ARE
QUICKLY MANUFACTURED
AND PROVIDED FOR US.
DANGEROUS IF WE HAPPEN
TO BE THINKING ABOUT--
YES. WE MUST
ALL CONTROL
OUR THOUGHTS.
DIFFICULT.
THE FORCE FIELD
IS OBVIOUSLY
UNDERGROUND
MANUFACTURING
THESE THINGS.
PASSAGES LEAD
TO THE SURFACE.
JUST FOR EXAMPLE,
WHEN RODRIGUEZ
THOUGHT OF A TIGER--
SPOCK...
WE'VE GOT TO GET BACK
TO THE LANDING PARTY
AND WARN THEM.
[AIRPLANE APPROACHES]
OOF!
OH!
AAH...
NO. NO!
SULU, RODRIGUEZ,
BARROWS,
FRONT AND CENTER.
SIR--
DON'T ASK
ANY QUESTIONS.
FACE FRONT, EVERYONE.
DON'T TALK...
DON'T BREATHE...
DON'T THINK...
YOU'RE AT ATTENTION.
CONCENTRATE ON THAT...
AND ONLY THAT.
CONCENTRATE.
CAPTAIN.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M THE CARETAKER
OF THIS PLACE,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU KNOW MY NAME?
BUT OF COURSE.
LIEUTENANT RODRIGUEZ...
LIEUTENANT SULU...
YEOMAN BARROWS,
AND MR. SPOCK.
WE'VE ONLY JUST
DISCOVERED THAT YOU DO
NOT UNDERSTAND ALL THIS.
THESE EXPERIENCES WERE
INTENDED TO AMUSE YOU.
AMUSE?
THAT'S YOUR WORD
FOR WHAT WE'VE
BEEN THROUGH?
BUT NONE OF THIS
IS PERMANENT.
HERE, YOU HAVE TO ONLY
IMAGINE YOUR FONDEST WISHES,
EITHER OLD ONES
WHICH YOU WISH TO RELIVE,
OR NEW ONES,
ANYTHING AT ALL--
BATTLE, FEAR,
LOVE, TRIUMPH...
ANYTHING THAT PLEASES YOU
CAN BE MADE TO HAPPEN.
THE TERM IS
AMUSEMENT PARK.
OF COURSE.
AN OLD EARTH NAME
FOR A PLACE WHERE
PEOPLE COULD GO
TO SEE AND DO
ALL SORTS OF
FASCINATING THINGS.
THIS ENTIRE PLANET
WAS CONSTRUCTED FOR
OUR RACE OF PEOPLE
TO COME...
AND PLAY.
PLAY?
AS ADVANCED
AS YOU OBVIOUSLY ARE,
AND YOU STILL PLAY?
YES, PLAY, MR. SULU.
THE MORE COMPLEX
THE MIND,
THE GREATER THE NEED
FOR THE SIMPLICITY
OF PLAY.
EXACTLY, CAPTAIN.
HOW PERCEPTIVE OF YOU.
THAT STILL DOESN'T
EXPLAIN THE DEATH
OF MY SHIP'S SURGEON.
POSSIBLY
BECAUSE NO ONE
HAS DIED, JIM.
I WAS TAKEN
BELOW THE SURFACE
FOR SOME RATHER
REMARKABLE REPAIRS.
IT'S AMAZING.
THEY'VE GOT
A FACTORY COMPLEX
DOWN THERE
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE.
THEY CAN BUILD
OR DO ANYTHING
IMMEDIATELY.
AND, UH, HOW DO YOU
EXPLAIN THEM?
OH. THEM. WELL...
I, UH...
I WAS THINKING
ABOUT A LITTLE CABARET
I KNOW ON RIGEL 2,
AND, UH, THERE WERE
THESE 2 GIRLS
IN A CHORUS LINE...
AND, WELL,
HERE THEY ARE.
WELL, AFTER ALL,
I AM ON SHORE LEAVE.
AND SO AM I.
YES. SO YOU ARE.
WELL, GIRLS, I SUPPOSE
YOU CAN TURN SOMETHING UP.
WE REGRET THAT
SOME OF YOU'VE BEEN
MADE UNCOMFORTABLE.
YOU SAY YOUR PEOPLE
BUILT ALL THIS.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT PLANET
ARE YOU FROM?
MY IMPRESSION IS
THAT YOUR RACE
IS NOT YET READY
TO UNDERSTAND US,
CAPTAIN.
I TEND TO AGREE.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
Uhura:
THIS IS THE BRIDGE,
CAPTAIN.
OUR POWER SYSTEMS
HAVE JUST COME BACK IN.
DO YOU REQUIRE
ASSISTANCE?
NO, EVERYTHING
IS IN ORDER,
LIEUTENANT.
STAND BY.
HOWEVER...
AYE AYE, SIR.
IF YOU WOULD USE
THE PROPER CAUTION,
THIS AMUSEMENT
PLANET OF OURS COULD
BE AN IDEAL PLACE
FOR YOUR PEOPLE TO
ENJOY THEMSELVES...
IF YOU WISH.
IT'S WHAT
THE DOCTOR ORDERED, JIM.
LIEUTENANT...
SIR?
COMMENCE TRANSPORTING
SHORE LEAVE PARTIES.
TELL THEM TO PREPARE
FOR THE BEST SHORE LEAVE
THEY'VE EVER HAD.
KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, I'LL GO
BACK ABOARD SHIP
AND TAKE OVER.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT
TO THE YOUNG LADY,
I'VE ALREADY HAD
AS MUCH SHORE LEAVE
AS I CARE FOR.
NO, MR. SPOCK.
I'LL GO. YOU--
ON THE OTHER HAND...
I'LL STAY
FOR A DAY OR TWO.
DID YOU ENJOY YOUR REST,
GENTLEMEN?
YES, WE...DID, MR. SPOCK.
I THINK WE DID.
INDEED WE DID,
MR. SPOCK.
MOST ILLOGICAL.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR ONE,
MR. SULU.