CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2821.5.
EN ROUTE TO MOCKUS 3
WITH A CARGO
OF MEDICAL SUPPLIES.
OUR COURSE LEADS US
PAST MURASAKI 312,
A QUASAR-LIKE FORMATION,
VAGUE, UNDEFINED.
PRICELESS OPPORTUNITY FOR
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATION.
ON BOARD IS GALACTIC
HIGH COMMISSIONER FERRIS,
OVERSEEING THE DELIVERY
OF THE MEDICINES
TO MOCKUS 3.
CAPTAIN TO
SHUTTLECRAFT GALILEO--
STAND BY, MR. SPOCK.
I REMIND YOU, CAPTAIN,
I'M ENTIRELY OPPOSED
TO THIS DELAY.
YOUR MISSION IS
TO GET THOSE EMERGENCY
MEDICAL SUPPLIES
TO MOCKUS 3 IN TIME
FOR THEIR TRANSFER
TO THE NEW PARIS COLONY.
NO PROBLEM,
COMMISSIONER.
AND MAY
I REMIND YOU...
THAT I HAVE STANDING ORDERS
TO INVESTIGATE
ALL QUASARS
AND QUASAR-LIKE PHENOMENA
WHEREVER THEY
MAY BE ENCOUNTERED.
BESIDES...
IT'S THREE DAYS
TO MOCKUS.
AND THE RENDEZVOUS
DOESN'T TAKE PLACE FOR FIVE.
I DON'T LIKE
TO TAKE CHANCES.
THE PLAGUE IS OUT OF
CONTROL ON NEW PARIS.
WE MUST GET THOSE
DRUGS THERE ON TIME.
NO PROBLEM.
CAPTAIN TO GALILEO--
ALL SYSTEMS CLEARED
FOR TAKEOFF.
POWER UP.
ALL INSTRUMENTS
ACTIVATED.
ALL READINGS NORMAL.
ALL GO.
LAUNCH SHUTTLECRAFT.
READINGS NORMAL...
ACCELERATION NORMAL...
PHASE ONE SEPARATION NORMAL.
POSITION?
3.7.
SIR, I--
MAKE UP YOUR MIND,
PLEASE, MR. LATIMER.
SIR, THIS INDICATOR'S
GONE CRAZY.
THAT'S TO BE EXPECTED,
MR. SPOCK.
QUASARS ARE
EXTREMELY DISRUPTIVE.
JUST HOW MUCH,
WE DON'T KNOW.
CONSIDERABLY, MR. BOMA.
MR. SPOCK, RADIATION
IS INCREASING.
STOP FORWARD MOMENTUM,
MR. LATIMER.
I CAN'T, SIR.
NOTHING HAPPENS.
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE.
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE--
COME IN, PLEASE.
[STATIC]
IONIC INTERFERENCE,
MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE BEING DRAWN
RIGHT INTO IT.
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE
OUT OF CONTROL,
BEING PULLED
DIRECTLY INTO THE HEART
OF MURASAKI 3-1-2.
BEING HIT
BY VIOLENT RADIATION
ON OUTER HULL.
COURSE, 3.25...
ANYTHING AT ALL?
NOTHING CLEAR,
CAPTAIN.
JUST A FEW WORDS ABOUT
BEING PULLED OFF COURSE.
TRY AND GET ME A FIX
ON THE GALILEO.
SCANNERS ARE BLANK,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE GETTING
A MASS OF READINGS
I'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
NOTHING MAKES SENSE.
[COMPUTER]
NEGATIVE IONIC
CONCENTRATION--
1.64 X 10
TO THE 9th POWER METERS,
RADIATION WAVELENGTH--
370 ANGSTROMS,
HARMONICS--UPWARD
ALONG ENTIRE SPECTRUM.
WHAT IS IT, CAPTAIN?
THAT THING OUT THERE
HAS IONIZED
THIS COMPLETE SECTOR.
NONE OF OUR
INSTRUMENTS WORK.
AT LEAST FOUR
COMPLETE SOLAR SYSTEMS
IN THE IMMEDIATE VICINITY.
AND OUT THERE, SOMEWHERE,
A 24-FOOT SHUTTLECRAFT,
OFF COURSE,
OUT OF CONTROL.
FINDING A NEEDLE
IN A HAYSTACK
WOULD BE
CHILD'S PLAY.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2821.7.
THE ELECTROMAGNETIC
PHENOMENON KNOWN
AS MURASAKI 312
WHIRLS LIKE SOME
ANGRY BLIGHT IN SPACE,
A DEPRESSIVE REMINDER
THAT SEVEN OF OUR SHIPMATES
STILL HAVE NOT BEEN HEARD FROM.
EQUALLY BAD,
THE EFFECT HAS RENDERED
OUR NORMAL
SEARCHING SYSTEMS USELESS.
WITHOUT THEM,
WE ARE BLIND...
AND ALMOST HELPLESS.
I WAS OPPOSED TO THIS
FROM THE VERY BEGINNING.
OUR FLIGHT TO MOCKUS 3 IS OF
THE VERY HIGHEST PRIORITY.
I'M AWARE OF THAT,
COMMISSIONER.
AT THE SAME TIME,
I HAVE CERTAIN SCIENTIFIC
DUTIES I MUST PERFORM,
AND INVESTIGATING
THE MURASAKI EFFECT
IS ONE OF THEM.
YES, BUT YOU'VE
LOST YOUR CREW.
WE HAVE TWO DAYS
TO FIND THEM.
TWO DAYS?
IN ALL THAT?
WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE ME DO,
TURN AROUND
AND LEAVE THEM THERE?
YOU SHOULDN'T
HAVE SENT THEM OUT
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
CAPTAIN, THERE'S ONE PLANET
IN THIS SOLAR SYSTEM
CAPABLE OF SUSTAINING
HUMAN LIFE.
TYPE M,
OXYGEN-NITROGEN,
AND IT'S LISTED
AS TAURUS 2.
UNEXPLORED.
AS FAR AS WE CAN DETERMINE
WITH OUR EQUIPMENT MALFUNCTION,
IT'S JUST ABOUT DEAD CENTER
OF THE MURASAKI EFFECT.
THANK YOU,
LIEUTENANT.
MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.
SET COURSE
FOR TAURUS 2.
AYE AYE, SIR.
[ELECTRICITY ZAPPING]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
SCOTTY?
BOMA?
YEAH.
NOW, THAT'S WHAT
I CALL A RIDE.
YEOMAN?
YEAH. JUST A LITTLE
BUMP ON THE HEAD.
UPSY-DAISY.
OH, THANK YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I CAN'T BE SURE,
BUT I'D SAY THAT...
THE MAGNETIC POTENTIAL
OF THE EFFECT WAS--
THANK YOU--
WAS SUCH THAT...
AS WE GATHERED
SPEED,
IT WAS MULTIPLIED
GEOMETRICALLY.
AND WE WERE SIMPLY
SHOT INTO THE CENTER
OF THE EFFECT,
LIKE A PROJECTILE.
I'D SAY YOUR EVALUATION
IS REASONABLE, MR. BOMA.
WHAT A MESS.
PICTURESQUE DESCRIPTIONS
WILL NOT MEND
BROKEN CIRCUITS, MR. SCOTT.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
YOUR WORK IS CUT OUT FOR YOU.
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN, PLEASE.
YOU DON'T REALLY EXPECT
TO GET AN ANSWER, DO YOU?
I EXPECT NOTHING,
MR. SCOTT.
IT IS MERELY LOGICAL TO TRY
ALL THE ALTERNATIVES.
DR. McCOY, A READING
ON THE ATMOSPHERE, PLEASE.
PARTIAL PRESSURE
OF OXYGEN,
70mm OF MERCURY,
NITROGEN--140.
BREATHABLE,
IF YOU'RE NOT RUNNING
IN COMPETITION.
JUST THE FACTS, DOCTOR.
TRACES OF ARGON,
NEON, KRYPTON.
ALL IN ACCEPTABLE
QUANTITIES.
HOWEVER, I WOULDN'T
RECOMMEND THIS PLACE
AS A SUMMER RESORT.
THANK YOU FOR
YOUR OPINION.
IT WILL BE DULY
NOTED.
YOU'RE RECORDING
THIS, YEOMAN?
OF COURSE, MR. SPOCK.
MR. SCOTT, IF YOU'LL
MAKE A SURVEY OF DAMAGE,
PLEASE.
LOGICAL.
GENTLEMEN, I THINK
WE SHOULD MOVE OUTSIDE,
MAKE ROOM FOR MR. SCOTT
TO DO HIS WORK.
MR. LATIMER, MR. GAETANO,
YOU WILL ARM YOURSELVES.
SCOUT OUT THE AREA,
KEEPING IN VISUAL
CONTACT WITH THE SHIP.
AYE AYE, SIR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OUR CHANCES ARE
OF CONTACTING
THE ENTERPRISE?
UNDER
PRESENT CONDITIONS,
EXTREMELY POOR.
BUT THEY'LL BE
LOOKING FOR US.
IF THE IONIZATION EFFECT
IS AS WIDESPREAD AS I
BELIEVE IT IS, DOCTOR,
THEY'LL BE SEARCHING FOR US
WITHOUT INSTRUMENTATION,
BY VISUAL CONTACT ONLY.
ON THOSE TERMS,
THIS IS
A VERY LARGE PLANET.
THEN YOU DON'T THINK
THEY'LL FIND US.
NOT AS LONG AS
WE'RE GROUNDED.
WE MAY BE HERE FOR A
VERY LONG TIME, DOCTOR.
NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
MR. SULU?
YES, CAPTAIN?
ANYTHING ON YOUR SCANNERS?
TOTALLY INOPERATIVE,
SIR. NO READINGS
AT ALL.
HAVE YOU TRIED TYING INTO
THE AUXILLARY POWER?
YES, SIR. NO CHANGE.
TRANSPORT ROOM...
THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
ARE THE TRANSPORTERS
BEAMING UP YET?
Man: NOT 100%, CAPTAIN.
WE BEAMED DOWN
SOME INNERT MATERIAL,
BUT IT CAME BACK IN A
DISSOCIATED CONDITION.
WE WOULDN'T DARE TRY IT
WITH PEOPLE.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
FLIGHT DECK,
PREPARE COLUMBUS
FOR IMMEDIATE EXIT...
FOR A SEARCH
OF THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
CORRELATE COORDINATES
FOR MR. SULU.
THANK YOU.
ANYTHING, UHURA?
ALL WAVELENGTHS DOMINATED
BY IONIZATION EFFECTS, SIR.
TRANSMISSION IS BLOCKED,
RECEPTION IMPOSSIBLE.
WELL, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE UNTIL 2823.8
TO CONTINUE THE SEARCH,
COMMISSIONER.
YOU DON'T REALLY
THINK YOU'LL HAVE
ANY LUCK, DO YOU?
LOOK, THESE PEOPLE
ARE MY FRIENDS
AND MY SHIPMATES.
I INTEND TO CONTINUE
THE SHIP'S SEARCH FOR THEM
UNTIL THE LAST
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
BUT NOT ONE SECOND
BEYOND THAT MOMENT.
IS THAT CLEAR?
IF IT ISN'T,
I SUGGEST
YOU LOOK AT BOOK 19,
SECTION 433,
PARAGRAPH 12--
I AM FAMILIAR
WITH THE REGULATIONS,
COMMISSIONER.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
YOUR AUTHORITY.
LAUNCH
SHUTTLECRAFT COLUMBUS.
WELL, I CAN'T SAY MUCH
FOR THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
BUT AT LEAST IT'S
YOUR BIG CHANCE.
MY BIG CHANCE?
FOR WHAT, DOCTOR?
COMMAND.
OH, I KNOW YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
YOU'VE NEVER
VOICED IT,
BUT YOU'VE ALWAYS
THOUGHT THAT LOGIC
WAS THE BEST
BASIS ON WHICH
TO BUILD COMMAND.
AM I RIGHT?
I AM A LOGICAL MAN,
DOCTOR.
IT'LL TAKE MORE THAN LOGIC
TO GET US OUT OF THIS.
PERHAPS, DOCTOR, BUT I KNOW
OF NO BETTER WAY TO BEGIN.
I REALIZE THAT COMMAND
DOES HAVE ITS FASCINATIONS,
EVEN UNDER CIRCUMSTANCES
SUCH AS THESE,
BUT I NEITHER ENJOY
THE IDEA OF COMMAND,
NOR AM I
FRIGHTENED OF IT.
IT SIMPLY EXISTS.
AND I WILL DO WHATEVER
LOGICALLY NEEDS TO BE DONE.
EXCUSE ME.
VERY BAD, MR. SPOCK.
IN WHAT WAY?
WE'VE LOST A GREAT
DEAL OF FUEL.
WE HAVE NO CHANCE AT ALL
TO REACH ESCAPE VELOCITY.
AND IF WE EVER
HOPE TO MAKE ORBIT,
WE'LL HAVE TO LIGHTEN OUR LOAD
BY AT LEAST 500 POUNDS.
THE WEIGHT
OF THREE GROWN MEN.
AYE, YOU COULD
PUT IT THAT WAY.
OR THE EQUIVALENT
WEIGHT IN EQUIPMENT.
DR. McCOY, WITH
VERY FEW EXCEPTIONS,
WE USE VIRTUALLY
EVERY PIECE OF EQUIPMENT
ABOARD THIS CRAFT
IN ATTAINING ORBIT.
THERE'S VERY LITTLE
EXCESS WEIGHT, EXCEPT
AMONG THE PASSENGERS.
YOU MEAN THREE OF US
MUST STAY BEHIND.
UNLESS THE SITUATION
CHANGES RADICALLY, YES.
AND WHO'S TO CHOOSE?
AS COMMANDING OFFICER,
THE CHOICE WILL BE MINE.
YOU WOULDN'T
BE INTERESTED
IN DRAWING LOTS?
VERY QUAINT IDEA,
MR. BOMA,
BUT I DO BELIEVE
I'M BETTER QUALIFIED
TO MAKE THE SELECTION
THAN ANY RANDOM
DRAWING OF LOTS.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
WHO?
MY CHOICE WILL
BE A LOGICAL ONE,
ARRIVED AT THROUGH
LOGICAL MEANS.
MR. SPOCK, LIFE AND DEATH
ARE SELDOM LOGICAL.
BUT ATTAINING A DESIRED
GOAL ALWAYS IS, DOCTOR.
NOW, GENTLEMEN, I SUGGEST
WE MOVE OUTSIDE
TO MAKE A FURTHER
EXAMINATION OF THE HULL
IN THE EVENT WE'VE
OVERLOOKED ANY MINOR DAMAGE.
IF ANY MINOR DAMAGE
WAS OVERLOOKED
IT WAS WHEN
THEY PUT HIS HEAD
TOGETHER.
NOT HIS HEAD, MR. BOMA.
HIS HEART.
[THRUMMING]
WHAT IS IT?
I--I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S FROM UP THERE.
NO, NO,
IT'S FROM BACK THERE.
IT'S EVERYWHERE.
IT'S ALL AROUND US!
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[GROWLING]
AAH!
COME ON, BOMA.
[ROAR]
WHAT WAS IT?
IT WAS SOMETHING HUGE,
TERRIBLE.
U-UP THERE.
I THINK I HIT IT.
DID YOU SEE
WHAT IT WAS?
VAGUELY. IT WAS
LIKE A GIANT APE.
POOR LATIMER.
AT LEAST IT WAS
QUICK FOR HIM.
WE'LL GET OFF ALL RIGHT.
NOTHING THERE.
I TELL YOU,
THERE WAS.
I DON'T DOUBT
YOUR WORD.
WELL, THERE MUST
BE SOMETHING.
I SWEAR I HIT IT.
XXX POINT.
SIR?
THIS, REMARKABLE
RESEMBLANCE TO
THE XXXX POINT
DISCOVERED 1925,
OLD WORLD CALENDAR,
NEW MEXICO,
NORTH AMERICA.
A BIT MORE CRUDE
ABOUT THE SHAFT,
I BELIEVE.
NOT VERY EFFICIENT.
NOT VERY EFFICIENT?
IS THAT ALL
YOU HAVE TO SAY?
AM I IN ERROR,
MR. BOMA?
YOU, ERROR?
IMPOSSIBLE.
THEN WHAT, MR. BOMA?
THERE'S A MAN
LYING THERE DEAD.
AND YOU TALK ABOUT
STONE SPEARS.
WHAT ABOUT LATIMER?
MY CONCERN FOR THE DEAD
WILL NOT BRING HIM
BACK TO LIFE,
MR. BOMA.
MR. SPOCK...
IN THE INTEREST
OF EFFICIENCY,
I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD
LEAVE HIS BODY HERE.
BRINGING HIM BACK
TO THE SHIP SHOULD
NOT INTERFER
WITH OUR
REPAIR EFFORTS.
IF YOU NEED
ASSISTANCE--
WE'LL DO IT.
GIVE ME A HAND
WITH LATIMER, WILL YOU?
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2822.3.
WE CONTINUE TO SEARCH...
BUT I FIND IT MORE
DIFFICULT EACH MOMENT
TO WARD OFF A SENSE
OF UTTER FUTILITY...
AND GREAT LOSS.
CAPTAIN, THE COLUMBUS
HAS RETURNED
FROM SEARCHING
QUADRANT 779X BY 534M.
RESULTS NEGATIVE.
HAVE THEM PROCEED
TO THE NEXT QUADRANT.
ANY WORD FROM ENGINEERING
ON OUR SENSORS?
THEY'RE WORKING
ON THEM, SIR.
STILL INOPERABLE.
WHAT ABOUT
THE TRANSPORTERS?
THEY'RE STILL
REPORTED UNSAFE.
THANK YOU,
LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN.
YES, COMMISSIONER?
I DON'T RELISH
THE THOUGHT OF ABANDONING
YOUR CREWMEN OUT THERE,
HOWEVER I MUST
REMIND YOU--
I HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN,
COMMISSIONER.
YOU'RE RUNNING
OUT OF TIME.
I HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN
THAT, COMMISSSIONER.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
TRY USING OVERLOAD POWER
ON THE TRANSPORTERS.
WE'VE GOT TO GET THEM
WORKING.
AYE AYE, CAPTAIN.
UHURA.
ORDER THE COLUMBUS
TO OPEN ITS COURSE
2 DEGREES ON EVERY
LAP FROM NOW ON.
CAPTAIN, 2 DEGREES
MEANS THEY'LL BE
OVERLOOKING
MORE THAN A DOZEN
TERRESTRIAL MILES
ON EACH SEARCH LOOP.
IT ALSO MEANS WE HAVE
A FIGHTING CHANCE
TO COVER THE MAJORITY
OF THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
MIND YOUR HELM,
MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.
24 MORE HOURS, CAPTAIN.
PERHAPS IF YOU
WERE TO CHANNEL THE
SECOND AUXILLARY TANK
THROUGH THE PRIMARY
INTAKE VALVE.
IT'S TOO DELICATE.
IT MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO TAKE THE PRESSURE
AS IT IS.
THIS SHOULD SAVE US
AT LEAST 50 POUNDS,
MR. SPOCK.
EXCELLENT,
DOCTOR.
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO
SCRAPE UP ANOTHER 100 POUNDS.
WHICH WOULD STILL
LEAVE US AT LEAST
150 POUNDS OVERWEIGHT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE SERIOUS
ABOUT LEAVING
SOMEONE BEHIND.
NOW, WHATEVER
IT IS OUT THERE--
IT IS MORE RATIONAL
TO SACRIFICE ONE LIFE
THAN SIX, DOCTOR.
I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT RATIONALITY.
YOU MIGHT BE
WISE TO START.
MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE READY.
FOR WHAT?
THE SERVICES
FOR LATIMER.
MR. BOMA,
WE'RE WORKING
AGAINST TIME.
THE MAN'S DEAD.
HE DESERVES A DECENT BURIAL.
YOU'RE THE CAPTAIN.
A FEW WORDS.
DOCTOR, PERHAPS YOU
KNOW THE CORRECT WORDS
FOR SUCH AN OCCASION.
MR. SPOCK,
THAT'S YOUR PLACE.
MY PLACE IS HERE.
IF YOU PLEASE,
DOCTOR.
NOW, LOOK,
WE MAY ALL DIE HERE.
AT LEAST LET US DIE
LIKE MEN, NOT MACHINES.
BY DEALING WITH
FIRST THINGS FIRST,
I HOPE TO INCREASE
OUR CHANCES
OF STAYING ALIVE.
WELL, MR. SCOTT.
IF YOU'LL GIVE ME A HAND
WITH THIS CONDUIT.
THE PRESSURE'S DROPPING.
WE'RE LOSING EVERYTHING.
WHAT HAPPENED?
ONE OF THE LINES GAVE.
THE STRAIN OF COMING
THROUGH THE ATMOSPHERE
AND THE ADDED LOAD
WHEN WE TRIED TO BYPASS.
YEAH, THAT'S DONE IT.
WE HAVE NO FUEL.
WELL, THAT WOULD SEEM
TO SOLVE THE PROBLEM
OF WHO TO LEAVE BEHIND.
CONSIDER THE ALTERNATIVES,
MR. SCOTT.
WE HAVE NO FUEL!
WHAT ALTERNATIVES?
MR. SCOTT, THERE ARE
ALWAYS ALTERNATIVES.
MR. SPOCK!
SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING OUTSIDE.
[THRUMMING]
WHAT DO THOSE
SUPERSENSITIVE EARS
MAKE OF THAT, MR. SPOCK?
WOOD--RUBBING ON
SOME KIND OF LEATHER.
THEY'RE GETTING READY.
THEY'LL ATTACK.
NOT NECESSARILY.
IT COULD BE A SIMPLE
TRIBAL RITE,
ASSUMING
A TRIBAL CULTURE.
NOT A TRIBAL CULTURE.
THEIR ARTIFACTS
ARE TOO PRIMITIVE.
MORE LIKELY A LOOSE
ASSOCIATION OF SOME SORT.
IF WE KNEW MORE
ABOUT THEM.
WE KNOW ENOUGH.
IF THEY'RE TRIBAL,
THEY'LL HAVE
A SENSE OF UNITY.
WE CAN USE THAT.
HOW, MR. BOMA?
BY HITTING THEM HARD.
GIVE THEM A BLOODY NOSE,
MAKE THEM THINK TWICE
ABOUT ATTACKING US.
YES. I AGREE.
IF WE STAND BY
AND DO NOTHING,
WE'RE JUST GIVING THEM
AN INVITATION
TO COME DOWN
AND SLAUGHTER US.
HMM. I'M FREQUENTLY APPALLED
BY THE LOW REGARD
YOU EARTHMEN HAVE FOR LIFE.
WELL, WE'RE
PRACTICAL ABOUT IT.
NOW, I SAY WE HIT THEM
BEFORE THEY HIT US.
MR. BOMA?
ABSOLUTELY.
DR. McCOY?
SEEMS LOGICAL TO ME.
IT DOES INDEED.
IT SEEMS LOGICAL
TO ME ALSO.
BUT TO TAKE LIFE
INDISCRIMINATELY...
THE MAJORITY.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN THE OPINION OF
THE MAJORITY, MR. GAETANO.
COMPONENTS MUST BE WEIGHED--
OUR DANGERS TO OURSELVES
AS WELL AS OUR DUTIES
TO OTHER LIFE FORMS,
FRIENDLY OR NOT.
THERE'S A THIRD COURSE.
THAT COULD
GET US KILLED.
I THINK NOT!
DR. McCOY,
YOU AND YEOMAN MEARS
RETURN TO THE SHIP.
ASSIST MR. SCOTT
IN ANY WAY POSSIBLE.
RIGHT.
WE'LL BE BACK SHORTLY.
GENTLEMEN,
YOU'LL FOLLOW MY ORDERS
TO THE LETTER,
FIRING ONLY
WHEN SO INSTRUCTED,
AND AT MY DESIGNATED
TARGETS.
NOW YOU'RE TALKING.
YOU'LL FIRE TO FRIGHTEN,
MR. GAETANO,
NOT TO KILL.
[THRUMMING]
OH, FOR THE...
YOU SAW WHAT THEY
DID TO LATIMER.
I AM IN COMMMAND,
MR. GAETANO.
THE ORDERS AND
THE RESPONSIBILITY
WILL BE MINE.
FOLLOW ME.
[RRRAARR]
[RRRARR]
THE MISTS, I...
I CAN'T SEE THEM.
I HEAR THEM.
THEY'RE DIRECTLY
AHEAD OF US.
SEVERAL, I BELIEVE.
DIRECT YOUR PHASERS
TO 2 O'CLOCK AND TO 10 O'CLOCK.
I SAY WE HIT THEM
DEAD ON.
YES, I KNOW, BUT FORTUNATELY,
I'M GIVING THE ORDERS.
TAKE AIM, PLEASE,
AND FIRE WHEN
I GIVE A SIGNAL.
FIRE.
CEASE FIRE.
THEY SHOULD THINK TWICE BEFORE
BOTHERING US AGAIN.
I STILL SAY WE SHOULD
HAVE KILLED THEM.
IT WAS NOT NECESSARY.
FEAR WILL DO FOR US
WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
MR. BOMA, YOU WILL RETURN
WITH ME TO THE GALILEO.
MR. GAETANO,
YOU REMAIN ON GUARD HERE.
KEEP IN CONTACT
WITH THE SHIP.
DID YOU FIND THEM?
YES, WE FOUND THEM.
THEY WON'T
BOTHER US AGAIN.
I HOPE NOT.
SCOTTY HAS AN IDEA.
IT'S DANGEROUS,
BUT IT MIGHT WORK.
GO, MR. SCOTT.
I CAN ADJUST
THE MAIN REACTOR
TO FUNCTION WITH
A SUBSTITUTE
FUEL SUPPLY.
THAT'S ALL VERY WELL,
BUT WE DON'T HAVE
A SUBSTITUTE SUPPLY.
AYE, WE DO.
OUR PHASERS.
I CAN ADAPT THEM AND
USE THEIR ENERGY.
IT'LL TAKE TIME,
BUT IT'S POSSIBLE.
THE TROUBLE IS THEY HAPPEN
TO BE OUR ONLY DEFENSE.
THEY ALSO SEEM TO BE
OUR ONLY HOPE.
AYE.
YEOMAN,
YOUR PHASER.
BUT WHAT IF
THE CREATURES
ATTACK AGAIN?
THEY WON'T ATTACK
FOR AT LEAST SEVERAL HOURS.
BY THEN, WITH LUCK,
WE'LL BE GONE.
IF I CAN GET
A FULL LOAD,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO ACHIEVE ORBIT
WITH ALL HANDS,
NOT THAT WE CAN
MAINTAIN IT LONG.
WE DON'T HAVE TO MAINTAIN IT
VERY LONG, MR. SCOTT.
IN LESS THAN 24 HOURS,
THE ENTERPRISE WILL BE
FORCED TO ABANDON ITS SEARCH
IN ORDER TO MAKE
A RENDEZVOUS.
IF WE CAN'T MAINTAIN ORBIT
AFTER THAT TIME,
IT WON'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
IF WE BURN UP
IN A DECAYING ORBIT
OR DIE HERE
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
WE SHALL SURELY DIE.
DOCTOR, YOUR PHASER.
GO TO WORK, MR. SCOTT.
AYE AYE, SIR.
[PHASER FIRING]
THEY CAME BACK
ALL RIGHT, SIR.
IN MY OPINION,
THE TRANSPORTERS ARE NOW
SAFE FOR HUMAN TRANSPORT.
GOOD.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
LANDING PARTIES 1, 2, AND 3,
REPORT TO TRANSPORTER ROOM
FOR IMMEDIATE BEAMING-DOWN
TO THE SURFACE
OF THE PLANET.
ORDNANCE CONDITION 1-A.
CAPTAIN,
IT'S A BIG PLANET.
IT'LL BE SHEER LUCK
IF OUR LANDING PARTIES
FIND ANYTHING.
I'M DEPENDING ON LUCK,
LIEUTENANT.
IT'S ALMOST THE ONLY TOOL
WE HAVE THAT WILL WORK.
[GROWLING]
AAHH!
TAKE THIS BACK
TO MR. SCOTT
FOR CONVERSION, PLEASE,
DOCTOR.
NOBODY KNOWS
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO GAETANO,
AND YOU
HAND OVER HIS PHASER
LIKE NOTHING'S
HAPPENED AT ALL.
AND GIVE THIS
TO MR. SCOTT
IN THE EVENT
I DON'T RETURN.
JUST WHERE
ARE YOU GOING?
I HAVE A CERTAIN...
SCIENTIFIC CURIOSITY
ABOUT WHAT'S BECOME
OF MR. GAETANO.
RETURN TO THE SHIP,
PLEASE.
I DON'T KNOW.
HE'LL RISK HIS NECK
LOCATING GAETANO,
THEN IF HE
FINDS HIM,
HE'S JUST AS LIABLE
TO ORDER HIM
TO STAY BEHIND.
YOU TELL ME.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THE SHIP WILL EVER LEAVE?
WELL, IT WON'T UNLESS WE
GET THESE PHASERS BACK.
[GROWLING]
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
THEY DIDN'T STAY FRIGHTENED
VERY LONG, DID THEY?
MOST ILLOGICAL REACTION.
WE DEMONSTRATED
OUR SUPERIOR WEAPONS.
THEY SHOULD HAVE FLED.
YOU MEAN THEY
SHOULD HAVE RESPECTED US?
OF COURSE.
MR. SPOCK, RESPECT
IS A RATIONAL PROCESS.
DID IT EVER
OCCUR TO YOU
THEY MIGHT REACT
EMOTIONALLY, WITH ANGER?
DOCTOR, I AM NOT
RESPONSIBLE FOR
THEIR UNPREDICTABILITY.
THEY WERE PERFECTLY
PREDICTABLE...
TO ANYONE
WITH FEELING.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
ADMIT IT, MR. SPOCK,
YOUR PRECIOUS LOGIC
BROUGHT THEM DOWN ON US.
WHY HAVEN'T THEY
DONE ANYTHING?
THEY'RE STUDYING US
FOR THE MOMENT.
ANOTHER PREDICTION,
MR. SPOCK?
MY OPINION,
MR. BOMA.
[CRASH]
SEAL THE WINDOWS!
STUDYING US, MR. SPOCK?
THEY SEEM TO LEARN
RATHER QUICKLY.
ALL RIGHT, SPOCK,
YOU HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS.
WHAT NOW?
MR. BOMA, YOUR TONE
IS INCREASINGLY HOSTILE.
MY TONE ISN'T THE ONLY THING
THAT'S HOSTILE, MR. SPOCK.
CURIOUS.
MOST ILLOGICAL.
AND I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF YOUR LOGIC!
WE COULD USE
A LITTLE INSPIRATION.
STRANGE. STEP BY STEP,
I HAVE MADE THE CORRECT
AND LOGICAL DECISIONS.
AND YET TWO MEN
HAVE DIED.
AND YOU'VE BROUGHT
OUR FURRY FRIENDS
DOWN ON US.
I DO SEEM TO HAVE
MISCALCULATED
REGARDING THEM
AND INCULCATED
RESENTMENT
ON YOUR PARTS.
THE SUM OF THE PARTS
CANNOT BE GREATER
THAN THE WHOLE.
A LITTLE LESS ANALYSIS
AND MORE ACTION--
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED,
MR. SPOCK.
HOW MUCH LONGER,
MR. SCOTT?
ANOTHER HOUR,
MAYBE TWO.
IT WON'T BE
LONG ENOUGH.
DOCTOR, A PHASER
CAN ONLY DRAIN SO FAST!
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
WE'LL BE ABLE TO HOLD OUT
UNDER THIS?
WE'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING.
YOU'VE GOT
YOUR HANDS FULL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2823.1.
OUR LANDING PARTIES
ARE ON THE SURFACE
OF TAURUS 2.
WE CONTINUE TO HOPE.
INSTRUMENTS ARE ONLY
SLOWLY RETURNING
TO AN OPERABLE CONDITION
AS THE ION STORM
SLOWLY DISPERSES.
ON THE SHIP, WE CAN
ONLY WAIT HELPLESSLY.
WHAT WORD
FROM THE SENSOR SECTION?
AT LAST REPORT THEY WERE
GETTING SOME READINGS--
I'M NOT INTEREST
IN THE LAST REPORT,
I WANT TO KNOW NOW!
YES, SIR.
YOU HAVE 2 HOURS
AND 43 MINUTES,
CAPTAIN.
I'M PERFECTLY AWARE
OF HOW MUCH TIME I HAVE LEFT.
I'M DELIGHTED, HOWEVER,
BUT I SHALL CONTINUE
TO REMIND YOU.
YOU DO THAT.
SIR, SENSOR SECTION
REPORTING.
STATIC INTERFERENCE
STILL CREATING
FALSE IMAGES.
ESTIMATES...
80% UNDEPENDABLE.
WHAT ABOUT
RADIO COMMUNICATION?
CLEARING SLOWLY.
STILL INCAPABLE
OF TRANSMISSION
OR RECEPTION.
WHAT DO YOU
INTEND TO DO?
DO? I INTEND TO
CONTINUE THE SEARCH,
FOOT BY FOOT,
INCH BY INCH,
BY CANDLELIGHT,
IF NECESSARY,
UNTIL THE LAST
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
IF YOU'D KEEP YOUR NOSE
OFF MY BRIDGE,
I'D BE THANKFUL.
I'M SURE THE AUTHORITIES
WILL BE PLEASED
BY YOUR DILIGENCE, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT SO SURE
THEY'LL APPRECIATE
THE WAY YOU ADDRESS
A HIGH COMMISSIONER.
I'M IN COMMAND HERE,
MR. FERRIS.
YOU ARE, CAPTAIN.
FOR ANOTHER 2 HOURS
AND 42 MINUTES.
MR. SCOTT, HOW MUCH POWER
DO WE HAVE LEFT
IN THE SHIP'S BATTERIES?
THEY'RE IN GOOD SHAPE,
BUT THEY WON'T LIFT US OFF,
IF THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE GETTING AT.
WILL THEY ELECTRIFY
THE EXTERIOR OF THIS SHIP?
THAT THEY WILL,
MR. SPOCK!
GET TO THE CENTER
OF THE SHIP.
DON'T TOUCH THE PLATES.
BE SURE YOU'RE INSULATED.
STAND BY.
ARE YOU READY, SCOTT?
READY, MR. SPOCK.
ALL RIGHT. GO!
AGAIN!
I CAN'T USE ANY MORE,
NOT AND BE SURE
OF IGNITION.
I BELIEVE WE'VE USED
ENOUGH, MR. SCOTT.
I SUGGEST YOU CONTINUE
DRAINING THE PHASERS.
AYE.
IT MUST HAVE WORKED.
FOR THE MOMENT.
FOR THE MOMENT?
THE MOMENT THEY DISCOVER
THEY'RE NOT SERIOUSLY HURT,
THEY'LL BE BACK.
MEANWHILE, PLEASE CHECK
THE AFT COMPARTMENT,
SEE IF THERE'S ANYTHING
ELSE YOU CAN UNLOAD
TO LIGHTEN THE SHIP.
MR. GAETANO'S BODY
IS BACK THERE.
HE'LL, OF COURSE
HAVE TO BE LEFT BEHIND.
NOT WITHOUT A BURIAL.
I WOULDN'T RECOMMEND IT.
THE CREATURES
WON'T BE FAR AWAY.
NOT WITHOUT A BURIAL,
MR. SPOCK.
IT WOULD EXPOSE
MEMBERS OF THIS CREW
TO UNNECESSARY PERIL.
I'LL TAKE THAT CHANCE.
YOU SEE, MR. SPOCK,
I WOULD INSIST
UPON A BURIAL
EVEN IF YOUR BODY
WAS BACK THERE.
MR. BOMA!
WELL,
I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF THIS MACHINE!
THAT'S ENOUGH!
GENTLEMEN.
ALL RIGHT, MR. BOMA,
YOU'LL HAVE YOUR BURIAL,
PROVIDED THE CREATURES
WILL PERMIT IT.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
LANDING PARTY NUMBER 2
HAS BEEN BEAMED BACK
ABOARD SHIP.
THEY HAVE CASUALTIES--
ONE DEAD, TWO INJURED.
PUT LIEUTENANT KELOWITZ
ON VISUAL.
KELOWITZ, CAPTAIN.
YOUR REPORT.
WE WERE ATTACKED,
CAPTAIN.
HUGE FURRY CREATURES.
I CHECKED WITH
ASTRAL ANTHROPOLOGY,
AND THEY'RE
ORDER 480-G, ANTHROPOID,
SIMILAR TO LIFE FORMS
DISCOVERED ON HANSON'S PLANET,
BUT MUCH LARGER.
10...12 FEET IN HEIGHT.
YOUR CASUALTIES?
WELL, ENSIGN O'NEAL
GOT A SPEAR THROUGH
THE BODY
BEFORE WE EVEN KNEW
THEY WERE AROUND.
LIUTENANT IMMAMOURA
HAS A DISLOCATED SHOULDER
AND SEVERE LACERATIONS,
BUT HE'LL MAKE IT, ALL RIGHT.
CAPTAIN, THE CREATURES
ARE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
IF THE GALILEO
IS DOWN ON THAT PLANET, I--
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
YOU BETTER REPORT
TO SICK BAY YOURSELF.
AYE AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK...
IF YOU CHECK
YOUR CHONOMETER,
YOU'LL SEE THAT IT IS
2823.8.
YOUR TIME IS UP.
BUT THEY'RE
STILL OUT THERE.
SO ARE THE PLAGUE
VICTIMS ON NEW PARIS.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I NOW ASSUME AUTHORITY
GRANTED ME
UNDER TITLE 15, GALACTIC
EMERGENCY PROCEDURES,
AND I ORDER YOU
TO ABANDON SEARCH.
THE COLUMBUS
HASN'T RETURNED YET.
I STILL HAVE TWO
SEARCH PARTIES OUT.
YOU'RE PROCRASTINATING,
CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
RECALL
YOUR SEARCH PARTIES
AND PROCEED TO
MOCKUS 3 IMMEDIATELY.
LIEUTENANT...
ORDER THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
TO IMMEDIATELY BEAM UP
THE TWO SEARCH PARTIES
FROM THE SURFACE.
ATTEMPT TO CONTACT
THE COLUMBUS.
I'M IN PARTIAL CONTACT
WITH THEM NOW, SIR.
THEN HAVE THEM
RETURN IMMEDIATELY.
MR. SULU...
PREPARE TO ABANDON SEARCH.
SET COURSE FOR MOCKUS 3.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
SUPPLEMENT.
THE SEARCH PARTIES
HAVE RETURNED TO THE SHIP,
AND THE COLUMBUS
IS ON ITS WAY BACK.
I HAVE BEEN COMPELLED
TO ABANDON THE SEARCH.
CAPTAIN,
THE SENSOR SECTION
SAYS THE BEAMS
ARE WORKING AGAIN.
WHAT ABOUT
THE OTHER SYSTEMS?
NO, SIR.
TOO MUCH INTERFERENCE.
CAPTAIN, COURSE SET
FOR MOCKUS 3.
STAND READY, MR. SULU.
HOW LONG BEFORE
THE COLUMBUS
COMES ON BOARD?
23 MINUTES, SIR.
23 MINUTES.
ENTERPRISE, THIS IS GALILEO.
COME IN, PLEASE.
ENTERPRISE.
NOTHING, SIR.
JUST IONIC INTERFERENCE.
THAT'S IT.
HOW ABOUT WEIGHT?
IF WE SHED EVERY OUNCE,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO ACHIEVE ORBIT.
AND HOW LONG
CAN WE HOLD IT?
A FEW HOURS,
NO LONGER.
BUT IF WE
TIME IT RIGHT,
WE CAN CUT OUT OF ORBIT
AND SAVE ENOUGH FUEL FOR
A CONTROLLED REENTRY.
TO LAND HERE AGAIN.
NOT A VERY ATTRACTIVE
POSSIBILITY.
WE HAVE VERY FEW
ALTERNATIVES, MR. SPOCK.
DR. McCOY, MR. BOMA.
WHEN CAN WE
LIFT OFF, SCOTT?
MAYBE EIGHT MINUTES
IF THE WEIGHT'S RIGHT.
GENTLEMEN,
THE SHIP
WILL LIFT OFF IN
EXACTLY 10 MINUTES.
YOU HAVE THAT LONG
TO BURY MR. GAETANO.
NOW, IT APPEARS
TO BE CLEAR OUTSIDE,
AT LEAST FOR THE MOMENT.
I'LL ASSIST YOU.
HURRY.
THE COLUMBUS
IS ABOARD, SIR.
THE FLIGHT HATCH
IS CLOSED.
TRANSPORTER ROOM
REPORTS
LAST OF THE LANDING PARTIES
HAVE BEAMED SAFELY UP.
ALL SYSTEMS REPORT
SECURED FOR WARP FACTORS.
MR. SULU, PROCEED ON COURSE
FOR MOCKUS 3...
AT SPACE NORMAL SPEED.
SPACE NORMAL, SIR?
THOSE ARE MY ORDERS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ORDER ALL SENSOR SECTIONS
TO DIRECT BEAMS AFT.
FULL FUNCTION,
CONTINUOUS OPERATION
UNTIL FURTHER ORDERS.
YES, SIR.
GET TO THE SHIP!
IMMEDIATE LIFTOFF!
AAH!
NO! GO BACK!
LIFT OFF!
GO BACK!
NO!
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT! GO!
GO! GO!
GO!
GO, SCOTT!
AYE AYE, SIR.
I TOLD YOU TO LIFT OFF!
DON'T BE A FOOL, MR. SPOCK.
WE COULDN'T LEAVE YOU OUT THERE!
GET US OFF, SCOTT!
WE SHOULD BE MOVING,
BUT WE'RE NOT.
QUITE RIGHT, MR. SCOTT.
THEY SEEM TO BE
HOLDING US DOWN.
ALL SYSTEMS ARE GO,
BUT WE'RE NOT MOVING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OUR BOOSTERS.
WE'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO HOLD ORBIT.
WOULD YOU
RATHER STAY HERE?
GO, MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE MOVING!
LET IT GO!
WE'RE OFF!
I REMIND YOU WE HAVE YET
TO ACHIEVE ORBIT,
NOR CAN WE
MAINTAIN IT LONG.
AN HOUR FROM NOW
WE MAY BE RIGHT BACK
WHERE WE STARTED.
GENTLEMEN,
BY COMING AFTER ME,
YOU MAY WELL HAVE
DESTROYED
WHAT SLIM CHANCE YOU HAD
FOR YOUR SURVIVAL.
THE LOGICAL THING
FOR YOU TO HAVE DONE
WAS TO HAVE
LEFT ME BEHIND.
MR. SPOCK,
REMIND ME TO TELL YOU
THAT I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF YOUR LOGIC.
THAT IS A MOST
ILLOGICAL ATTITUDE.
ORBIT IN ONE MINUTE,
MR. SCOTT.
FUEL STATUS?
15 POUNDS PSI.
APPROXIMATELY ENOUGH
FOR ONE ORBIT, SIR.
AFTER THAT?
TAPPING OUR BOOSTERS
ENDED OUR LAST CHANCE
FOR A SOFT LANDING.
YOU MEAN A BURN-UP?
THAT IS THE USUAL END
OF A DECAYING ORBIT.
I DON'T WANT TO DIE
UP HERE.
INFINITELY PREFERABLE
TO THE KIND OF DEATH
WE'D BE GRANTED
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
I SHOULD THINK.
I ADMIRE YOUR ABILITY
TO MAKE SO MEASURED A CHOICE.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU SAID A WHILE AGO
THAT THERE WERE
ALWAYS ALTERNATIVES.
DID I?
I MAY HAVE BEEN
MISTAKEN.
WELL, AT LEAST
I LIVED LONG ENOUGH
TO HEAR THAT.
IS THERE ANYTHING
WE CAN DO?
THE ENTERPRISE
IS SURELY ON COURSE
FOR MOCKUS 3 BY NOW.
I, FOR ONE, DO NOT
BELIEVE IN ANGELS.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
SO ENDS YOUR FIRST COMMAND.
YES.
MY FIRST COMMAND.
ORBIT ATTITUDE,
MR. SPOCK.
WITH OUR PRESENT FUEL,
THAT GIVES US
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
[SWITCHES ON RADIO]
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE.
GALILEO TO ENTERPRISE,
COME IN, PLEASE.
MR. SPOCK!
[JET BLAST]
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE JETTISONED THE FUEL
AND IGNITED IT.
WE NEED THAT FUEL
TO MAINTAIN ORBIT.
ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
PERHAPS, MR. BOMA.
HOW LONG WE GOT
NOW, SCOTTY?
THE ORBIT
WILL START DECAYING
AS SOON AS
THE FUEL'S EXHAUSTED,
SAY, 6 MINUTES.
[VOICES ON
RADIO TRANSMISSION]
CAPTAIN! THERE'S
SOMETHING THERE
ON THE SCREEN,
AT TAURUS 2.
SENSORS.
A METEORITE?
NO. IT'S HOLDING
A LATERAL LINE.
THERE IT IS AGAIN.
HOLDING STEADY,
CAPTAIN.
180 DEGREES ABOUT,
MR. SULU.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTACT TRANSPORTER ROOM.
ALL BEAMS READY.
FULL NORMAL SPEED.
A DISTRESS SIGNAL?
IT'S LIKE SENDING UP
A FLARE.
MR. SPOCK...
THAT WAS A GOOD GAMBLE.
PERHAPS IT WAS
WORTH IT.
NO ONE OUT THERE
TO SEE IT.
ORBIT DECAYING,
MR. SPOCK.
10 SECONDS TO ATMOSPHERE.
IT MAY BE THE LAST ACTION
YOU'LL EVER TAKE, MR. SPOCK,
BUT IT WAS ALL YOU.
TOTALLY ILLOGICAL.
THERE WAS NO CHANCE.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I MEAN.
IT'S GETTING HOT.
TRANSPORTERS
LOCKED IN, SIR.
ACTIVATE BEAMS.
[COUGHING]
WHATEVER IT WAS,
CAPTAIN,
IT JUST BURNED UP
IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
[BEEPING]
CAPTAIN! TRANSPORTER ROOM
JUST BEAMED UP FIVE PERSONS.
ALIVE AND WELL.
MR. SULU,
PROCEED ON COURSE
TO MOCKUS 3.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 1.
AYE AYE, SIR.
WARP FACTOR 1.
UH, MR. SPOCK.
CAPTAIN.
THERE'S REALLY SOMETHING
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
ABOUT ALL OF THIS,
AND MAYBE YOU CAN
EXPLAIN IT TO ME,
LOGICALLY, OF COURSE.
WHEN YOU JETTISONED THE FUEL
AND YOU IGNITED IT,
YOU KNEW THAT THERE WAS
VIRTUALLY NO CHANCE
OF IT BEING SEEN,
AND YET YOU DID IT ANYHOW.
NOW,
THAT WOULD SEEM TO ME
TO BE AN ACT
OF DESPERATION.
QUITE CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
NOW, WE ALL KNOW,
AND I'M SURE THE DOCTOR
WOULD AGREE WITH ME
THAT DESPERATION
IS A HIGHLY EMOTIONAL
STATE OF MIND.
HOW DOES YOUR
WELL-KNOWN LOGIC
EXPLAIN THAT?
QUITE SIMPLY, CAPTAIN.
I EXAMINED THE PROBLEM
FROM ALL ANGLES,
AND IT WAS
PLAINLY HOPELESS.
LOGIC INFORMED ME THAT
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
THE ONLY POSSIBLE ACTION
WOULD HAVE TO BE ONE
OF DESPERATION.
LOGICAL DECISION,
LOGICALLY ARRIVED AT.
AHA.
I SEE.
YOU MEAN
YOU REASONED
THAT IT WAS TIME
FOR AN EMOTIONAL
OUTBURST.
WELL, I...
WOULDN'T PUT IT
IN EXACTLY THOSE TERMS,
CAPTAIN, BUT...
THOSE ARE ESSENTIALLY
THE FACTS.
YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO ADMIT
THAT FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN YOUR LIFE,
YOU COMMITTED
A PURELY HUMAN,
EMOTIONAL ACT?
NO, SIR.
[CHUCKLING]
[KIRK LAUGHING]
MR. SPOCK,
YOU'RE A STUBBORN MAN.
YES, SIR.
[ALL LAUGHING]