[ MUSIC ]
ALL CLEAR AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS INDICATE ZERO REGISTER.
FORWARD READINGS, MR. SPOCK.
BAROMETRIC READING,
NO SIGNIFICANCE CHANGE,
ZERO SPACE DENSITY.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR THREE,
MR. SULU.
COLONY BETA SIX
WANTS THEIR SUPPLIES.
WE'LL GET ACROSS THIS VOID
IN A HURRY.
VOID, STAR DESERT.
THE WORD CONJURES UP PICTURES
OF DUNES, OASES, MIRAGES.
SUNLIGHT, PALM TREES.
WE'RE 900 LIGHT YEARS
FROM THAT KIND OF DESERT, BONES.
THE PRECISE MEANING
OF THE WORD DESERT
IS A WATERLESS,
BARREN WASTELAND.
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
YOUR ROMANTIC NOSTALGIA
FOR SUCH A PLACE.
DOESN'T SURPRISE ME, MR. SPOCK.
I CAN'T IMAGINE A MIRAGE
EVER DISTURBING
THOSE MATHEMATICALLY PERFECT
BRAIN WAVES OF YOURS.
THANK YOU, DR. McCOY.
MOVING ON SCHEDULE
INTO QUADRANT 904,
BETA SIX IS EIGHT DAYS DISTANT.
SOMETHING, MR. SPOCK?
UNUSUAL, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOW GETTING A SIZABLE
SPACE DISPLACEMENT READING.
CAN YOU VERIFY THAT, NAVIGATOR?
NO, SIR.
FORWARD SWEEPS ARE NEGATIVE.
WAIT! VERIFIED, SIR.
WE MUST BE IN SOME SORT
OF LIGHT WARP
OR WE WOULD HAVE PICKED IT UP
EARLIER.
PUT IT ON VISUAL.
IRON SILICA BODY, PLANET SIZE,
MAGNITUDE 1E.
WE'LL BE PASSING CLOSE.
INCONCEIVABLE THIS BODY HAS GONE
UNNOTED ON ALL OUR RECORDS.
AND YET HERE IT IS.
NO TIME TO INVESTIGATE.
SCIENCE STATIONS
GATHER DATA FOR COMPUTER BANKS.
UHURA, NOTIFY THE DISCOVERY
ON SUBSPACE RADIO.
STRONG INTERFERENCE ON SUBSPACE,
CAPTAIN.
THE PLANET MUST BE
A NATURAL RADIO SOURCE.
LET'S GET OUT OF ITS RANGE.
VEER 40 DEGREES TO STARBOARD,
MR. SULU.
40 DEGREES.
SULU!
MR. SPOCK, THEY'RE GONE!
EMERGENCY! FULL REVERSE POWER!
[ MUSIC ]
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION:
TO EXPLORE STRANGE, NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
SHIP'S LOG, STARDATE 2124.5.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK REPORTING
FOR CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
WE ARE ORBITING
THE LONE UNRECORDED PLANET
IN THE STAR DESERT.
FOR FOUR HOURS, WE HAVE MADE
EVERY POSSIBLE INSTRUMENT SWEEP,
BUT CAPTAIN KIRK
AND HELMSMAN SULU
REMAIN UNACCOUNTED FOR.
I HAVE PLACED THE SHIP
ON RED ALERT.
WE'VE SEARCHED AGAIN
FROM STEM TO STERN.
IF THEY'RE NOT DOWN
ON THAT PLANET,
THEY'RE NOWHERE.
NO SIGN OF HUMAN LIFE
ON THE SURFACE, SIR,
UNLESS THE INSTRUMENTS
AREN'T FUNCTIONING.
FUNCTION IS NORMAL.
CONTINUE SENSOR SWEEPS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HAVE YOU CHECKED ALL WAVE BANDS?
ALL OF THEM, MR. SPOCK.
NO RESPONSE.
WITH DUE RESPECT, SIR,
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO TRANSPORT TO THE SURFACE
IMMEDIATELY
AND CARRY OUT SEARCH.
I SECOND DESALLE'S REQUEST.
WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
THE DECISION WILL BE MINE,
DOCTOR.
I HAVE THE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR YOUR SAFETY.
MR. JAEGER, DESCRIBE
YOUR GEOPHYSICAL FINDINGS
FOR THE SURFACE BELOW.
NO DETECTABLE SOIL
OR VEGETATION, EXTREMELY HOT,
TOXIC ATMOSPHERE
SWEPT BY TORNADIC STORMS,
CONTINUOUS VOLCANIC ERUPTIONS,
DEADLY TO ANY LIFE FORM
SUCH AS WE KNOW IT
WITHOUT OXYGEN
AND LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
ESTIMATE SURVIVAL TIME
OF TWO UNPROTECTED INDIVIDUALS
DOWN THERE.
NOT VERY LONG.
MR. SPOCK, LOOK.
GREETINGS AND FELICITATIONS.
HMM. SEND THIS, LIEUTENANT.
USS ENTERPRISE TO SIGNALER
ON PLANET SURFACE.
IDENTIFY SELF.
[ BEEPING ]
HIP HIP HOORAH?
AND I BELIEVE
IT'S PRONOUNCED TALLYHO.
SOME KIND OF A JOKE, SIR?
I'LL ENTERTAIN ANY THEORIES,
MR. DESALLE, ANY AT ALL.
ONE THING IS CERTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY, THERE'S LIFE
ON THAT PLANET.
YOU'RE QUITE CORRECT, DOCTOR.
PREPARE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
REQUEST ASSIGNMENT
TO THE SEARCH PARTY, SIR.
NO, MR. SCOTT.
NEITHER YOU NOR I
CAN BE SPARED HERE.
MR. DESALLE, YOU'LL EQUIP
THE LANDING PARTY
WITH FULL COMMUNICATIONS,
ARMAMENT AND LIFE SUPPORT GEAR.
MR. JAEGER,
YOUR GEOPHYSICAL KNOWLEDGE
MAY BE CRUCIAL DOWN THERE.
DR. McCOY WILL ACCOMPANY.
IF THOSE PECULIAR SIGNALS
ARE COMING FROM CAPTAIN KIRK
OR LIEUTENANT SULU,
THEIR RATIONALITY
IS IN QUESTION.
DISMISSED.
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
NO MORE MESSAGES FROM BELOW,
SIR,
BUT I'VE LOCKED ON
TO THEIR ORIGINAL SOURCE.
VERY GOOD.
TRANSMIT COORDINATES
TO MR. SCOTT.
ONCE ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
YOU'LL ESTABLISH CONTACT WITH US
IMMEDIATELY.
USE THE LASER BEACON
IF NECESSARY.
READY, SCOTT?
READY, MR. SPOCK.
ACTIVATE.
[ TRANSPORTER BEAM ]
WHERE ARE YOUR STORMS, JAEGER?
ATMOSPHERE EXACTLY THE SAME
AS OURS.
DESALLE TO ENTERPRISE,
DESALLE TO ENTERPRISE.
IT DOESN'T FUNCTION.
WE'RE CUT OFF.
[ BEEPING ]
NO RESPONSE.
KEEP TRYING WITH YOURS.
[ BEEPING ]
SOMETHING'S BLOCKING THE BEACON.
GOT TO FIND OPEN GROUND.
JAEGER! McCOY!
[ MUSIC ]
IN THE NAME OF HEAVEN,
WHERE ARE WE?
LOOK!
[ MUSIC ]
THERE'S NO READING.
THEY'RE LIKE WAXWORKS FIGURES.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ MUSIC ]
I MUST SAY THEY MAKE A PERFECTLY
EXQUISITE DISPLAY PAIR,
BUT I SUPPOSE
YOU WANT THEM BACK NOW.
WHERE ARE WE?
WELCOME TO AN ISLAND OF PEACE
ON MY STORMY LITTLE PLANET
OF GOTHOS.
WHAT HAPPENED?
FILL ME IN.
YOU DISAPPEARED
FROM THE BRIDGE AFTER SULU.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU
FOR FOUR HOURS.
YOU MUST EXCUSE MY WHIMSICAL WAY
OF FETCHING YOU HERE.
BUT WHEN I SAW YOU PASSING BY,
I SIMPLY COULD NOT RESIST.
I'M CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK OF
THE UNITED STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
AH, SO YOU ARE THE CAPTAIN
OF THESE BRAVE LADS.
MY GREETINGS AND FELICITATIONS,
CAPTAIN.
SO GOOD OF YOU AND YOUR OFFICERS
TO DROP IN.
ABSOLUTELY SMASHING.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHERE DO YOU COME FROM?
GENERAL TRELANE, RETIRED.
AT YOUR SERVICE, SIRS.
MY HOME IS YOUR HOME.
[ MUSIC ]
WE'VE LOST CONTACT
WITH THE SHIP, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE TRAPPED HERE.
I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW DELIGHTED I AM
TO HAVE VISITORS
FROM THE VERY PLANET
THAT I'VE MADE MY HOBBY.
YES, BUT ACCORDING
TO MY OBSERVATIONS,
I DIDN'T THINK YOU CAPABLE
OF SUCH VOYAGES.
NOTICE THE PERIOD, CAPTAIN,
900 LIGHT YEARS FROM EARTH.
IT'S WHAT MIGHT BE SEEN
THROUGH A VIEWING SCOPE
IF IT WERE POWERFUL ENOUGH.
AH, YES.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING IN
ON THE DOINGS
ON YOUR LIVELY LITTLE EARTH.
THEN YOU'VE BEEN LOOKING IN
ON THE DOINGS 900 YEARS PAST.
OH, REALLY?
HAVE I MADE AN ERROR IN TIME?
HOW FALLIBLE OF ME.
OH, I DID SO WANT TO MAKE YOU
FEEL AT HOME.
I'M QUITE PROUD OF THE DETAIL.
GENERAL TRELANE...
RETIRED, SIR.
JUST SQUIRE TRELANE NOW.
AND YOU MAY CALL ME SQUIRE.
YES, I RATHER FANCY THAT.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE
HAVE YOU IMPRISONED US HERE?
IMPRISONED? NONSENSE.
YOU'RE MY GUESTS.
YOU SEE, I JUST FINISHED
MY STUDIES OF YOUR CURIOUS
AND FASCINATING SOCIETY.
YOU CAME BY
AT THE MOST PROPITIOUS MOMENT.
I WANT TO KNOW
ALL ABOUT YOUR CAMPAIGNS,
YOUR BATTLES,
YOUR MISSIONS OF CONQUEST.
OUR MISSIONS ARE PEACEFUL,
NOT TO CONQUEST.
WHEN WE DO BATTLE,
IT IS ONLY BECAUSE
WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BUT THAT'S THE OFFICIAL STORY,
EH?
I MUST ASK YOU
TO LET US GO BACK TO OUR SHIP.
OH, I WOULDN'T HEAR OF IT.
YOU SHALL JOIN ME IN A REPAST.
I WANT TO LEARN
ALL ABOUT YOUR FEELINGS ON WAR
AND KILLING AND CONQUEST,
THAT SORT OF THING.
DO YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE ONE
OF THE FEW PREDATOR SPECIES
THAT PREYS EVEN ON ITSELF?
NOT YET.
PUT IT ON STUN,
NOT TO KILL, DESALLE.
DESALLE, DID YOU SAY?
[ SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
MY ANCESTRY IS FRENCH, YES.
AH, MONSIEUR!
[ SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
YOU KNOW, I ADMIRE YOUR NAPOLEON
VERY MUCH.
THIS IS MR. DESALLE,
OUR NAVIGATOR;
DR. McCOY, OUR MEDICAL OFFICER;
MR. SULU, OUR HELMSMAN;
AND CARL JAEGER, METEOROLOGIST.
WELCOME, GOOD PHYSICIANER
AND HONORABLE SIR.
IS HE KIDDING?
UND, OFFICER JAEGER...
[ SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
I'M A SCIENTIST,
NOT A MILITARY MAN.
OH, COME NOW.
WE'RE ALL MILITARY MEN
UNDER THE SKIN.
AND HOW WE DO LOVE OUR UNIFORMS.
WHAT AN INTERESTING WEAPON
YOU'VE GOT THERE.
DO LET ME SEE IT.
YES.
NOW, LET ME SEE.
HOW DOES THIS WORK?
AH, YES.
THIS WON'T KILL, AND THIS WILL.
OH.
[ PHASER FIRING ]
OH, HOW MARVELOUS.
DEVASTATING.
WHY, THIS COULD KILL MILLIONS.
WHO WILL YOU START WITH,
MY CREW?
ARE WE YOUR NEXT TARGETS?
OH, HOW ABSOLUTELY TYPICAL
OF YOUR SPECIES.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND SOMETHING,
SO YOU BECOME FEARFUL.
NOW, DO LET ME ANTICIPATE
YOUR NEXT QUESTION.
YOU WANT TO KNOW
HOW I MANAGED ALL OF THIS.
THAT'S CORRECT.
[ SMIRKS ]
WE, MEANING I AND OTHERS, HAVE,
TO STATE THE MATTER BRIEFLY,
PERFECTED A SYSTEM
BY WHICH MATTER
CAN BE TRANSFERRED TO ENERGY
AND BACK TO MATTER AGAIN.
LIKE THE TRANSPORTER SYSTEM
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE.
OH, A CRUDE EXAMPLE
OF AN INFINITELY
MORE SOPHISTICATED PROCESS.
YOU SEE, WE NOT ONLY TRANSPORT
MATTER FROM PLACE TO PLACE,
BUT WE CAN ALTER ITS SHAPE
AT WILL.
THIS DRAWING ROOM,
DID YOU CREATE IT
BY REARRANGING MATTER
ON THIS PLANET?
QUITE.
I SEE.
HOW DID YOU MANAGE...
DEAR CAPTAIN, YOUR INQUIRIES
ARE BECOMING TIRESOME.
I WANT YOU TO BE HAPPY.
FREE YOURSELF OF CARE.
LET'S ENJOY OURSELVES
IN THE SPIRIT
OF MARTIAL GOOD FELLOWSHIP.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
WE'RE GETTING OUT OF HERE.
TUT, TUT, TUT!
YOU'RE BEING QUITE RUDE.
YOU CAN'T GO.
APPARENTLY, YOU NEED
ANOTHER DEMONSTRATION
OF MY AUTHORITY.
YES, QUITE.
[ MUSIC ]
[ COUGHING ]
NOW, THAT'S A SAMPLE
OF THE ATMOSPHERE OF THIS PLANET
OUTSIDE MY KINDLY INFLUENCE.
NOW, YOU WILL BEHAVE YOURSELF
HERE, CAPTAIN, WON'T YOU?
OR I SHALL BE VERY, VERY ANGRY.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 2125.7.
SCIENCE OFFICER SPOCK
REPORTING FOR CAPTAIN KIRK.
WE'VE COMPLETED 14th ORBIT
OF THIS PLANET
WITHOUT ESTABLISHING CONTACT
WITH OUR MISSING OFFICERS
OR THE PARTY SENT TO FIND THEM.
SUBSPACE COMMUNICATIONS
REMAIN BLOCKED.
HOWEVER, BY DIVERTING
THE IMPULSE POWER
TO OUR SENSORS,
WE HAVE MADE THEM OPERABLE,
AND WE HAVE DETECTED
ONE SMALL AREA ON THE SURFACE
WHICH SEEMS RELATIVELY STABLE.
AYE, IT'S THERE, MR. SPOCK.
PEACEFUL AS EARTH,
BUT HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN IT?
I DON'T, MR. SCOTT.
IT SIMPLY EXISTS.
ARTIFICIAL PERHAPS
OR A FREAK OF NATURE,
BUT THE FACT REMAINS THAT LIFE
CAN EXIST IN THAT AREA.
AYE, IT COULD.
BUT IT COULDN'T MOVE
AROUND MUCH.
APPLY A FINE TUNING
ON OUR SENSORS.
LOCATE ANY LIFE FORMS
IN THAT STABLE AREA.
EVEN IF WE FIND ANY,
IT DOESN'T FOLLOW
THAT IT WOULD BE OUR PEOPLE.
AFFIRMATIVE.
BUT IF THE CAPTAIN IS DOWN THERE
AND ALIVE,
THAT'S WHERE HE'LL HAVE TO BE.
WE'LL ATTEMPT TO TRANSPORT UP
ANY LIVING BEINGS
OUR SENSORS DETECT.
SHOOTING IN THE DARK, MR. SPOCK?
OR STAND BY AND DO NOTHING,
MR. SCOTT.
[ MUSIC ]
AND THIS, OF COURSE,
IS AN ARRAY OF YOUR BATTLE FLAGS
AND PENNANTS
DATING BACK TO THE CRUSADES,
TO HANNIBAL'S INVADERS,
THE GRECIAN WAR GALLEYS
AND THE HOARDS OF PERSIA.
CAN'T YOU IMAGINE IT, CAPTAIN,
THE THOUSANDS OF MEN
MARCHING OFF TO THEIR DEATHS
SINGING BENEATH THESE BANNERS?
DOESN'T IT MAKE YOUR BLOOD
RUN SWIFTLY?
CAPTAIN, WHERE COULD HE
POSSIBLY COME FROM?
[ MUSIC ]
WHO IS THIS MANIAC?
BETTER SAY, WHAT IS HE?
I MONITORED HIM.
WHAT I FOUND WAS UNBELIEVABLE.
NOT ALIVE?
NOT IN THE WAY WE DEFINE LIFE.
NO TRACE, ZERO.
YOU MEAN, IT SHOWS HE'S DEAD?
IT DOESN'T EVEN SHOW
THAT HE EXISTS AT ALL,
ALIVE OR DEAD.
NOTICE THE WOOD FIRE, CAPTAIN,
BURNING STEADILY,
EMBER BED GLOWING?
IT DOESN'T GIVE OFF
ANY HEAT AT ALL.
FIRE WITHOUT HEAT,
MISTAKING ALL THIS
FOR PRESENT-DAY EARTH
WITHOUT TAKING INTO ACCOUNT
THE TIME DIFFERENTIAL.
WHATEVER WE'RE DEALING WITH,
HE CERTAINLY
ISN'T ALL KNOWLEDGEABLE.
HE MAKES MISTAKES.
DISCUSSING DEEP-LAID PLANS,
I'LL WAGER.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I CANNOT WAIT
TO SEE THEM EVOLVE.
TRELANE, WE HAVEN'T PLANNED--
TUT, TUT.
DO NOT THINK THAT I DEPLORE
YOUR MARTIAL VIRTUE OF DECEPTION
AND STRATAGEM.
QUITE THE CONTRARY.
I HAVE NOTHING BUT ADMIRATION
FOR YOUR WHOLE SPECIES.
IF YOUR ADMIRATION IS GENUINE,
YOU MUST HAVE RESPECT
FOR OUR SENSE OF DUTY TOO.
OUR SHIP HAS NEED OF US.
WE HAVE TASKS TO PERFORM.
OH, I CAN'T LET YOU GO NOW.
I WAS GETTING A BIT BORED
UNTIL YOU CAME.
YOU MUST STAY.
I INSIST.
FOR HOW LONG?
UNTIL THIS IS OVER, OF COURSE.
UNTIL WHAT IS OVER?
DEAR CAPTAIN, SO MANY QUESTIONS.
MAKE THE MOST
OF AN UNCERTAIN FUTURE.
ENJOY YOURSELVES TODAY.
TOMORROW MAY NEVER COME AT ALL.
TRELANE, EVEN IF WE WANTED
TO STAY,
OUR COMPANIONS ARE MISSING US.
YES.
I MUST EXPERIENCE
YOUR SENSE OF CONCERN,
YOUR GRIEF AT THE SEPARATION.
THERE ARE 400 MEN AND WOMEN
ABOARD THAT SHIP.
WOMEN?
DO YOU MEAN THAT YOU ACTUALLY
HAVE MEMBERS OF THE FAIRER SEX
AMONG YOUR CREW?
OH, HOW CHARMING.
AND THEY MUST BE
ALL VERY BEAUTIFUL.
AND I SHALL BE SO VERY GALLANT
TO THEM.
HERE, LET ME FETCH THEM DOWN
AT ONCE.
NO.
NO?
THIS GAME HAS GONE ON
LONG ENOUGH.
THOSE ARE CRUCIAL
OPERATING PERSONNEL.
YOU CAN'T--
I CAN DO ANYTHING I WANT.
I SHOULD THINK THAT YOU
WOULD HAVE REALIZED THAT BY NOW.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN, RECEIVING
A TRANSPORTER SIGNAL.
TRANSPORTER SIGNAL?
WHAT DOES HE MEAN?
YOU MUST TELL ME.
IT MEANS, TRELANE,
THE PARTY'S OVER,
THANKS TO MR. SPOCK.
WAIT! I WON'T HAVE THIS!
I HAVEN'T DISMISSED YOU YET!
STOP! I WON'T HAVE THIS!
EVERYONE'S STATIONED.
REPORT, MR. SPOCK.
HOW WERE OUR SCANNERS
ABLE TO PENETRATE
THAT RADIATION FIELD?
THEY DIDN'T, CAPTAIN,
NOT CLEARLY.
WE MERELY BEAMED UP
ALL LIFE FORMS IN A GIVEN AREA.
WHICH MEANS TRELANE
IS NOT A LIFE FORM
AS WE KNOW IT
OR HE'D BE BEAMING THROUGH NOW.
PREPARE TO WARP OUT OF HERE
AT ONCE, MAXIMUM SPEED.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN, I WAS SO WORRIED.
SCOTTY, WE'RE GONNA NEED
EVERY OUNCE OF YOUR ENGINES.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A HUNDRED MILLION MILES
BETWEEN US AND THAT MAD MAN.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
I'M QUAKING, BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER IT'S WITH LAUGHTER
OR TERROR.
DOCTOR, WHAT WAS IT?
WHAT WAS DOWN THERE?
WELL, IT WAS A--OH, FORGET IT.
LOOK!
[ MUSIC ]
WHERE ARE ALL YOUR WEAPONS,
CAPTAIN?
DON'T YOU DISPLAY YOUR WEAPONS?
TRELANE.
DON'T FRET, CAPTAIN.
I'M ONLY A BIT UPSET WITH YOU.
BUT THIS MR. SPOCK
YOU MENTIONED,
THE ONE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THAT UNSEEMLY IMPUDENT ACT
OF TAKING YOU FROM ME,
WHICH IS HE?
I AM SPOCK.
SURELY NOT AN OFFICER.
HE ISN'T QUITE HUMAN, IS HE?
MY FATHER
IS FROM THE PLANET VULCAN.
AND ARE ITS NATIVES PREDATORY?
NOT GENERALLY,
BUT THERE HAVE BEEN EXCEPTIONS.
REALLY?
YOU WILL SEE TO HIS PUNISHMENT?
ON THE CONTRARY,
I COMMEND HIS ACTION.
BUT I DON'T LIKE HIM.
GET OFF MY SHIP.
OH, ROT!
YOU'RE ALL GOING BACK WITH ME.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
NONSENSE.
I HAVE AN ABSOLUTELY
ENCHANTING SOJOURN
ON GOTHOS PLANET FOR ALL OF YOU,
AND YOU SHAN'T SPOIL IT FOR ME.
ANYWAY, THE DECOR
OF MY DRAWING ROOM
IS MUCH MORE APPROPRIATE
AND TASTEFUL.
DON'T YOU AGREE?
NO.
BUT SO MUCH MORE FITTING,
HONORABLE SIR.
YOU...
OH, WHAT PRIMITIVE FURY.
WHY, HE'S THE VERY SOUL
OF SUBLIME SAVAGERY.
TRELANE, LET HIM GO.
WE HAVEN'T EVEN GOT OUR PHASERS.
YES, OF COURSE.
I FORGET THAT I SHOULDN'T
FRIGHTEN YOU TOO MUCH.
BUT I WARN YOU.
YOU CAN'T PROVOKE ME AGAIN.
COME, EVERYONE.
LET'S FORGET YOUR BAD MANNERS.
LET'S BE FULL OF MERRY TALK
AND SALLIES OF WIT.
WE HAVE VICTUALS
TO DELIGHT THE PALATE
AND BRAVE COMPANY
TO DELIGHT THE MIND.
COME, DOCTOR, DO PARTAKE.
AH, YOU'VE BEEN QUITE DERELICT
IN YOUR SOCIAL DUTIES, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVEN'T INTRODUCED ME
TO THE CHARMING CONTINGENT
OF YOUR CREW.
THIS IS GENERAL TRELANE.
RETIRED.
BUT IF YOU PREFER,
YOU MAY ADDRESS ME
AS THE LONELY SQUIRE OF GOTHOS,
DEAR LADIES.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
OF COMMUNICATIONS.
AH, A NUBIAN PRIZE.
TAKEN ON ONE OF YOUR RAIDS
OF CONQUEST, NO DOUBT, CAPTAIN?
NO DOUBT.
SHE HAS THE MELTING EYES
OF THE QUEEN OF SHEBA,
THE SAME LOVELY COLORING.
AND THIS.
IS THIS THE FACE
THAT LAUNCHED A THOUSAND SHIPS
AND BURNT THE TOPLESS TOWERS
OF ILIUM?
FAIR HELEN,
MAKE ME A MORTAL WITH A KISS.
YEOMAN TERESA ROSS.
I BELIEVE YOU HAVE MET
OUR SCIENCE OFFICER, MR. SPOCK.
YOU DO REALIZE, DON'T YOU,
THAT IT'S IN DEFERENCE
TO THE CAPTAIN
THAT I BROUGHT YOU HERE?
AFFIRMATIVE.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
IF I LIKE YOUR TONE.
IT'S MOST CHALLENGING.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE DOING,
CHALLENGING ME?
I OBJECT TO YOU.
I OBJECT TO INTELLECT
WITHOUT DISCIPLINE.
I OBJECT TO POWER
WITHOUT CONSTRUCTIVE PURPOSE.
OH, MR. SPOCK, YOU DO HAVE
ONE SAVING GRACE AFTER ALL.
YOU'RE ILL-MANNERED.
THE HUMAN HALF OF YOU, NO DOUBT.
AH, COME, MY LITTLE WOOD NYMPH.
WON'T YOU DANCE WITH YOUR SWAY?
GIVE US SOME SPRIGHTLY MUSIC,
MY DEAR GIRL.
OH, I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO PLAY THIS.
OF COURSE, YOU DO.
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN, HOW FAR DO WE GO ALONG
WITH THIS CHARADE?
UNTIL WE CAN THINK OUR WAY OUT.
MEANWHILE, WE ACCEPT
THIS HOSPITALITY.
WELL, YOU SHOULD TASTE
THIS FOOD.
SCRAW WOULD TASTE BETTER
THAN HIS MEAT
AND WATER 100 TIMES BETTER
THAN HIS BRANDY.
NOTHING HAS ANY TASTE AT ALL.
IT MAY BE UNAPPETIZING, DOCTOR,
BUT IT IS VERY LOGICAL.
THERE'S THAT MAGIC WORD AGAIN.
DOES YOUR LOGIC FIND THIS
FASCINATING, MR. SPOCK?
FASCINATING IS A WORD I USE
FOR THE UNEXPECTED.
IN THIS CASE, I SHOULD THINK
INTERESTING WOULD SUFFICE.
YOU DON'T FIND THIS UNEXPECTED,
MR. SPOCK?
THAT HIS FOOD HAS NO TASTE,
HIS WINE NO FLAVOR?
NO.
IT SIMPLY MEANS THAT TRELANE
KNOWS ALL OF THE EARTH FORMS,
BUT NONE OF THE SUBSTANCE.
AND THAT HE'S FALLIBLE.
HE CAN'T BE ALL POWERFUL,
WHICH MEANS HE HAS SOMETHING
HELPING HIM.
EVIDENTLY.
A MACHINE? A DEVICE?
SOMETHING WHICH DOES
THESE THINGS FOR HIM.
AH, MY DEAR,
DON'T WE MAKE A GRACEFUL PAIR?
EXCEPT FOR ONE SMALL DETAIL.
THAT DRESS HARDLY MATCHES
THIS CHARMING SCENE.
AH, YES, THAT'S MORE
OF WHAT WE WANT.
THE DASHING WARRIOR
AND HIS ELEGANT MAIDEN.
THAT MIRROR,
PART OF HIS AUDIENCE, HIS EGO.
HE NEVER WANDERS FROM IT.
IS IT EGO OR SOMETHING ELSE?
EXPLAIN.
THE MIRROR.
WHAT ABOUT IT?
YOU NOTED YOURSELF HE NEVER
GETS VERY FAR AWAY FROM IT.
I SUPPOSE IT COULD BE VANITY.
NO, NO, MR. SPOCK.
THAT'S NOT THE REASON.
WHAT KIND OF A MACHINE
COULD DO THESE THINGS?
A MACHINE WITH THE ABILITY
TO TURN ENERGY INTO MATTER
GUIDED BY THOUGHT WAVES.
IT WOULD HAVE
A VERY COMPLEX MEMORY BANK
AND BE EXTREMELY SOPHISTICATED.
LIKE A COMPUTER, ONLY MUCH MORE.
COULD THE MACHINE
THAT MAINTAINS THE ENVIRONMENT
IN THIS IMMEDIATE AREA
BE KEPT IN THIS HOUSE?
I THINK NOT.
A DEVICE CAPABLE OF KEEPING OUT
THIS PLANET'S NATURAL ATMOSPHERE
WOULD BE IMMENSE.
GOOD. I AGREE.
THAT LEAVES ME FREE.
FREE, CAPTAIN?
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN, MR. SPOCK,
I THINK I CAN TURN
HIS LIGHTS OFF AT THE SOURCE.
DON'T BE TOO UPSET
BY WHAT YOU SEE, GENTLEMEN.
AFTER ALL, HIS ACTIONS
ARE THOSE OF AN IMMATURE,
UNBALANCED MIND.
I OVERHEARD THAT REMARK,
CAPTAIN.
I'M AFRAID
I'LL HAVE TO DISPENSE WITH YOU.
YOU ONLY HEARD PART OF IT.
I JUST STARTED.
OH?
YES.
I WANT YOU
TO LEAVE MY CREWMEN ALONE.
I WANT YOU TO LEAVE
MY CREW WOMEN ALONE TOO.
YOU'RE NOT TO DANCE WITH HIM.
I DON'T LIKE IT.
DOES IT ACTUALLY MAKE YOU ANGRY,
CAPTAIN?
I DON'T WANT YOU
ACCEPTING HIS GIFTS EITHER.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE DON'T DO THIS.
WELL, I DO BELIEVE
THAT THE DEAR CAPTAIN
IS JEALOUS OF ME.
I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU BELIEVE.
JUST KEEP YOUR HANDS OFF HER.
OH, HOW CURIOUSLY HUMAN.
HOW WONDERFULLY BARBARIC.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH
OF YOUR INSULTING ATTENTIONS
TO HER.
OF COURSE, YOU HAVE.
AFTER ALL,
THAT'S THE ROOT OF THE MATTER,
ISN'T IT?
YOU FIGHT FOR THE ATTENTION,
THE ADMIRATION,
THE POSSESSION OF WOMEN.
IF IT'S FIGHTING THAT YOU WANT,
YOU MAY HAVE IT.
ARE YOU CHALLENGING ME
TO A DUEL?
IF YOU HAVE THE COURAGE.
OH, THIS IS BETTER
THAN I'D PLANNED.
I SHALL NOT SHIRK
AN AFFAIR OF HONOR.
A MATCHED SET JUST LIKE THE PAIR
THAT SLEW
YOUR HEROIC ALEXANDER HAMILTON.
AND, CAPTAIN, I NEVER MISS.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 2126.1,
DELAYED REPORT.
THE WHOLE BRIDGE CREW
ARE THE UNWILLING GUESTS
OF THE CREATURE
WHO CALLS HIMSELF TRELANE.
WE ARE WEAPONLESS, POWERLESS,
AND OUR ONLY HOPE OF ESCAPE
WITH THE ENTERPRISE
LIES IN PLAYING HIS GAMES.
I'VE DECIDED TO MAKE MY MOVE
WITH THE FIELD OF HONOR GAME
AND EVERYTHING DEPENDS
ON MY ONE CHANCE
WITH THE ANCIENT DUELING PISTOL.
OH, HOW FASCINATING.
I'M PARTY
TO AN ACTUAL HUMAN DUEL.
ARE YOU READY?
QUITE READY, SIR.
WE SHALL TEST
EACH OTHER'S COURAGE,
AND THEN?
AND THEN WE SHALL SEE.
ENOUGH TALK.
LET'S GET ON WITH IT.
AS YOU WILL, SIR.
HONOR WILL BE SERVED, EH?
OH, WAIT!
AS THE ONE CHALLENGED,
I CLAIM THE FIRST SHOT.
WE SHOOT TOGETHER.
IT'S MY GAME AND MY RULES.
BUT IF YOU NEED
TO BE PERSUADED...
[ MUSIC ]
ALL RIGHT.
CAPTAIN?
[ GUNSHOT ]
AND NOW, CAPTAIN,
HOW DO YOU HAVE THE EXPRESSION?
MY FATE IS IN YOUR HANDS.
[ GUNSHOT ]
YOU'VE RUINED EVERYTHING!
THE MACHINE.
CAPTAIN, SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE
IS CLEARING.
TRY TO CONTACT THE SHIP.
OH, THE REMARKABLE TREACHERY
OF THIS SPECIES.
GO ON, TRELANE, LOOK AT IT.
IT'S OVER.
YOUR POWER IS BLANKED OUT.
YOU'RE FINISHED.
YOU'VE EARNED MY WRATH.
GO BACK.
GO BACK TO YOUR SHIP,
ALL OF YOU, AND PREPARE.
YOU'RE ALL DEAD MEN,
YOU ESPECIALLY, CAPTAIN.
TRELANE.
EVERYONE, WE'RE GETTING OUT
OF HERE NOW.
[ BEEPING ]
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
COMMENCE BEAMING UP.
MAXIMUM SPEED.
[ MUSIC ]
SET COURSE FOR COLONY BETA SIX.
LAID IN, SIR.
FULL POWER ACCELERATION
FROM ORBIT, MR. SCOTT.
Full power, sir.
EMERGENCY WARP AT THE EARLIEST
POSSIBLE MOMENT, MR. SULU.
STANDING BY TO WARP SPEED.
SHALL I MAKE A FULL REPORT
TO SPACEFLEET COMMAND, SIR?
NOT YET.
THEY MAY TRACE OUR BEAM.
WAIT UNTIL WE'RE WELL OUT
OF RANGE.
CAN WE KNOW WHAT HIS RANGE IS,
CAPTAIN?
WE CAN TAKE AN EDUCATED GUESS
AT THE POINT WE FIRST ENTERED
THEIR SOLAR SYSTEM.
STILL NO SIGN OF PURSUIT.
INSTRUMENTS CLEAR, SIR.
GOOD.
MAY I TAKE A MOMENT TO CHANGE?
YES, I THINK YOU MIGHT.
TURN IN YOUR GLASS SLIPPERS.
THE BALL IS OVER.
GLADLY, CAPTAIN.
HARD TO BELIEVE
THAT IT NEVER HAPPENED.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE ABOUT TO WARP.
LIGHT BODY AHEAD.
[ MUSIC ]
COLLISION COURSE.
HARD TO PORT, MR. SULU.
THAT WAS THE PLANET GOTHOS,
CAPTAIN.
GOTHOS.
MR. SULU,
HAVE WE BEEN GOING IN CIRCLES?
NO, SIR.
ALL INSTRUMENTS SHOW ON COURSE.
GOTHOS AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
HARD OVER, MR. SULU.
CAT AND MOUSE GAME.
WITH US AS THE MOUSE.
THERE IT IS AGAIN, DEAD AHEAD.
90 DEGREES TO STARBOARD,
MR. SULU.
TURNING, CAPTAIN.
NOT VEERING OFF FROM IT.
90 DEGREES SOUTHPORT, MR. SULU.
ADJUST.
TURN COMPLETED
AND STILL ACCELERATING
TOWARD THE PLANET.
OR IT TOWARD US.
DECELERATE INTO ORBIT.
PREPARE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE NOT BEAMING DOWN.
YES, I AM, DR. McCOY.
I AM GOING TO SEE
OUR PLAYFUL MR. TRELANE
AND WHATEVER IT TAKES
TO MAKE HIM GIVE UP OUR SHIP.
STAND BY, COMMUNICATIONS.
MR. SPOCK, IF YOU DON'T RECEIVE
A MESSAGE FROM ME
WITHIN THE HOUR,
LEAVE THE VICINITY AT ONCE.
NO TURNING BACK.
THE PRISONER MAY APPROACH
THE BENCH.
TRELANE.
ANY ATTEMPT TO DEMONSTRATIONS
WILL WEIGH AGAINST YOU
WITH THE COURT.
AND THIS TIME,
MY INSTRUMENTALITY
IS UNBREAKABLE.
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF YOUR GAMES.
OH, THE ABSURDITY
OF THESE INFERIOR BEINGS.
AND NOW, CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK,
YOU STAND ACCUSED
OF THE HIGH CRIME OF TREASON
AGAINST A SUPERIOR AUTHORITY,
CONSPIRACY AND THE ATTEMPT
TO FOMENT INSURRECTION.
HOW DO YOU PLEAD?
I HAVEN'T COME TO PLEAD
IN YOUR COURT, TRELANE.
I WARN YOU,
ANYTHING YOU MIGHT SAY
HAS ALREADY BEEN TAKEN DOWN
IN EVIDENCE AGAINST YOU.
I'VE COME FOR ONE PURPOSE,
TO GET BACK MY SHIP.
IRRELEVANT.
WE'VE MADE YOU ANGRY
WITH OUR WILL TO SURVIVE,
HAVE WE?
UNCALLED FOR.
THEN VENT YOUR ANGER ON ME
ALONE!
I WAS THE ONE
THAT LED THE OTHERS.
I WAS THE ONE THAT SHOT OUT
YOUR MIRROR MACHINE.
AND DID YOU REALLY THINK
THAT WAS THE ONLY MEDIUM
OF INSTRUMENTALITY
AT MY COMMAND?
I TOOK THAT CHANCE.
I'M WILLING TO PAY THE PRICE
FOR CHANCING WRONG.
OH, THEN YOU DO ADMIT
TO THE CHARGES?
YES! ANYTHING!
JUST ALLOW THE ENTERPRISE
TO CONTINUE ITS JOURNEY,
YOU POMPOUS...
IMMATERIAL!
THOSE PEOPLE HAVE DONE YOU
NO HARM.
INADMISSIBLE!
WE'RE LIVING BEINGS,
NOT PLAYTHINGS
FOR YOUR AMUSEMENT!
SILENCE!
THIS TRIAL IS OVER!
YOU ARE GUILTY.
ON ALL COUNTS, YOU ARE GUILTY.
AND ACCORDING TO YOUR OWN LAWS,
THIS COURT HAS NO CHOICE
IN FIXING PUNISHMENT.
YOU WILL HANG BY THE NECK,
CAPTAIN,
UNTIL YOU ARE DEAD, DEAD, DEAD!
[ MUSIC ]
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 2126.3.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK REPORTING.
STILL NO WORD FROM CAPTAIN KIRK
ON THE SURFACE BELOW US.
WAITING TIME IS ALMOST UP.
I WILL SOON BE FORCED
TO ATTEMPT DEPARTURE
AS PER INSTRUCTIONS.
UNTIL A MOMENT AGO,
I DIDN'T THINK IT POSSIBLE,
BUT IT WAS.
I DID IT.
I WAS ANGRY.
I ACTUALLY EXPERIENCED
GENUINE RAGE.
THIS EXPERIMENT
HAS BEEN SUCCESSFUL.
I'M GLAD
YOU WEREN'T DISAPPOINTED.
WHY, CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE STILL ANGRY.
WOULD THAT I COULD HAVE
SUSTAINED THAT MOMENT.
AH, NO MATTER.
DO YOU HAVE A LAST REQUEST?
TRELANE, IF YOU THINK
I'M GONNA CHEERFULLY
AND OBEDIENTLY STICK MY HEAD
IN THAT NOOSE...
YOU STILL HAVEN'T LEARNED.
YOU HAVE NO CHOICE.
OH, THIS IS BECOMING
QUITE TIRESOME.
IT'S ALL SO VERY EASY.
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM, TRELANE.
EVERYTHING IS EASY.
IT'S GIVING YOU A BAD HABIT.
YOU'RE NOT AWARE OF IT,
BUT YOU HAVE IT.
EH?
YOU DON'T THINK, TRELANE.
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
YOU MISS OPPORTUNITIES
LIKE YOUR ANGER BEFORE
AND MINE RIGHT NOW.
OH, YOU ENJOY IT,
BUT YOU COULDN'T HAVE
ACCOMPLISHED IT WITHOUT ME.
AND YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE YOU'RE A BUMBLING,
INEPT FOOL.
TAKE CARE NOW.
HERE YOU HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY
TO EXPERIENCE SOMETHING
REALLY UNIQUE,
AND YOU'RE WASTING IT.
YOU WANNA COMMIT MURDER?
GO AHEAD.
BUT WHERE'S THE SPORT
IN A SIMPLE HANGING?
SPORT?
YES, THE TERROR OF MURDER.
THE SUSPENSE, THE FUN.
OH, I'M INTRIGUED.
GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST?
A PERSONAL CONFLICT BETWEEN US.
NOT LIKE THE DUEL BEFORE,
BUT THE REAL THING.
THE STAKES?
A HUMAN LIFE, MINE.
[ LAUGHS ]
OH.
YES!
THAT'S THE IDEA.
OH, THEN YOU APPROVE?
YES!
BUT YOU CAN DO BETTER THAN THAT.
THERE'S STILL NOT ENOUGH SPORT
IN JUST KILLING ME WITH A SWORD.
I KNOW.
THAT WILL BE DULL.
WE'LL HAVE TO HAVE SOMETHING
MORE FANCIFUL.
LET ME SEE.
A HUNT, A ROYAL HUNT,
PREDATOR AGAINST PREDATOR.
NOW, YOU MAY GO HIDE
IN THE FOREST,
ANYWHERE YOU LIKE,
AND I SHALL SEEK.
HOW DOES THAT STRIKE YOU,
CAPTAIN?
IT STRIKES ME VERY WELL.
BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO MAKE IT
WORTH MY WHILE, TRELANE.
WHY NOT UP THE STAKES?
WHAT STAKES?
YES.
WHILE WE'RE PLAYING OUR GAME,
FREE MY SHIP.
LET IT CONTINUE ON ITS WAY.
IN RETURN, I'LL GIVE YOU
A CONTEST YOU'LL REMEMBER.
ALWAYS BACK TO YOUR SHIP.
OH, WELL, IF IT WILL ADD SPICE
TO THE PURSUIT,
I ACCEPT YOUR TERMS, CAPTAIN.
REMEMBER, YOU MUST TRY
NOT TO LET ME FIND YOU
TOO QUICKLY.
LET ME NOTIFY THE ENTERPRISE
THAT IT CAN GO.
AT YOUR CONVENIENCE.
[ BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE, ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS KIRK.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
GET THE SHIP AWAY
AS FAST AS YOU CAN.
I'LL TRY AND GIVE YOU THE TIME
YOU NEED.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[ MUSIC ]
[ BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU MUST TRY HARDER, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS TOO EASY.
[ BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
TOUCH, CAPTAIN, TOUCH.
I MUST CONFESS,
YOU SCORED FIRST.
BUT AFTER ALL,
I NEVER PLAYED THIS GAME BEFORE.
AND NOW, LET'S HAVE AT IT AGAIN.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ BEEPING ]
ENTERPRISE.
HA! TALLYHO!
AH, YOU MADE A NOBLE FIGHT
OF IT, CAPTAIN.
REMEMBER, TRELANE,
YOU PROMISED TO LET MY SHIP GO.
YES, BUT THIS IS SUCH SPORT.
I MUST FETCH ALL THE OTHERS BACK
TO PLAY.
SO THIS IS VICTORY.
IT HAS A SWEET TASTE.
DOWN, CAPTAIN.
ON YOUR KNEES.
YOU HAVEN'T WON, TRELANE.
I HAVE.
I COULD RUN YOU THROUGH.
BUT YOU HAVEN'T WON ANYTHING.
ON YOUR KNEES, CAPTAIN.
NO!
DOES IT STILL TASTE AS SWEET?
I ORDER YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN BEATEN.
BUT I'M NOT DEFEATED.
I ORDER YOU. I ORDER YOU.
YOU BROKE MY SWORD.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT TO LEARN
ABOUT WINNING, TRELANE.
YOU DARE TO DEFY ME.
IN FACT, YOU'VE GOT A LOT
TO LEARN ABOUT EVERYTHING,
HAVEN'T YOU?
I'LL FIX YOU FOR THAT.
YOU CHEATED.
YOU HAVEN'T PLAYED
THE GAME RIGHT.
I'LL SHOW YOU.
Trelane.
NO!
NO.
YOU SAID I COULD HAVE
THIS PLANET FOR MY VERY OWN.
This has gone far enough.
BUT YOU ALWAYS STOP ME
WHEN I'M HAVING FUN.
You're disobedient and cruel.
We've told you before.
Time to come in now, Trelane.
BUT I DON'T WANNA COME IN,
AND I WON'T.
I'M A GENERAL,
AND I WON'T LISTEN TO YOU.
Enough, Trelane.
Come along.
BUT WHY?
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
I WAS JUST PLAYIN'.
We said come along!
BUT I HAVEN'T STUDYING
MY PREDATORS YET.
This is not studying them.
If you cannot take proper care
of your pets,
you cannot have them at all.
BUT I WAS WINNING.
I WAS WINNING.
They're beings, Trelane.
They have spirit.
They're superior.
NO, NO.
YOU SAW.
You'll grow up, Trelane.
You'll understand.
Now, come along.
AW, BUT YOU SAID I COULD.
YOU PROMISED.
I NEVER HAVE ANY FUN.
Stop that nonsense at once,
or you'll not be permitted
to make any more planets.
AW, BUT YOU SAW.
I WAS WINNING.
I WOULD HAVE WON, HONEST.
No, Trelane.
- No, Trelane.
I WOULD HAVE. I WOULD HAVE.
I WOULD HAVE.
I WOULD. I WOULD.
Captain, we regret
that the life paths of yourself
and your companions
have been disturbed.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHO IS TRELANE?
You must forgive our child.
The fault is ours
for indulging him too much.
He will be punished.
We would not have let him
intercept you
had we realized
your vulnerability.
Forgive us, Captain.
We will maintain
your life support conditions
while you return to your ship.
Please accept our apologies.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN TO ENTERPRISE.
Captain, we're receiving you.
BEAM ME UP, MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE FREE TO GO.
[ MUSIC ]
WARPING DOWN, CAPTAIN.
OUR WARP FACTOR, FOUR.
PUSH CHANNELS CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
COLONY BETA SIX CLEARS US
FOR NORMAL APPROACH, SIR.
NORMAL ORBIT
APPROACH PROCEDURES, MR. SULU.
CAPTAIN?
MR. SPOCK,
STILL THINKING ABOUT TRELANE,
IS THAT IT?
FOR THE RECORD, CAPTAIN,
HOW DO WE DESCRIBE HIM?
PURE MENTALITY?
FORCE OF INTELLECT?
EMBODIED ENERGY?
SUPER BEING?
HE MUST BE CLASSIFIED, SIR.
GOD OF WAR, MR. SPOCK.
WELL, I HARDLY
FIND THAT FITTING.
THEN A SMALL BOY,
AND A VERY NAUGHTY ONE AT THAT.
IT WILL MAKE A STRANGE ENTRY
IN THE LIBRARY BANKS.
WELL, THEN HE WAS
A VERY STRANGE, SMALL BOY.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
HE WAS PROBABLY DOING THINGS
COMPARABLE TO THE SAME
MISCHIEVOUS PRANKS YOU PLAYED
WHEN YOU WERE A BOY.
MISCHIEVOUS PRANKS, CAPTAIN?
YES, DIPPING LITTLE GIRLS' CURLS
IN INKWELLS,
STEALING APPLES
FROM THE NEIGHBOR'S TREES,
TYING CANS ON--
FORGIVE ME, MR. SPOCK.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN BETTER.
I SHALL BE DELIGHTED, CAPTAIN.
[ MUSIC ]