YOU'LL ENJOY
COMMODORE TRAVERS.
HE SETS A GOOD TABLE.
I WONDER
IF HE BROUGHT
HIS PERSONAL CHEF
ALONG WITH HIM
TO CESTUS 3.
PROBABLY. RANK
HATH ITS PRIVILEGES.
HOW WELL WE BOTH
KNOW THAT, HUH?
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
SCOTTY.
SIR.
KIRK HERE.
TRAVERS, JIM.
WE'RE WAITING.
GOOD, UH, COMMODORE.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
BE SURE TO
BRING ALONG YOUR
TACTICAL PEOPLE.
I'VE GOT
AN INTERESTING
PROBLEM FOR THEM.
WE'LL BEAM DOWN
IMMEDIATELY,
COMMODORE. KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, I WONDER WHY
HE IS SO INSISTENT
THAT OUR TACTICAL AIDES
COME DOWN.
HIS COLONY IS
ISOLATED, EXPOSED,
OUT ON THE EDGE
OF NOWHERE.
HE PROBABLY WANTS
ADDITIONAL ADVICE.
PERHAPS, CAPTAIN,
BUT NEVERTHELESS I--
SPOCK, ISN'T IT ENOUGH
THE COMMODORE
IS FAMOUS FOR
HIS HOSPITALITY?
I, FOR ONE, COULD USE
A GOOD NONRECONSTITUTED MEAL.
DOCTOR, YOU ARE
A SENSUALIST.
YOU BET YOUR
POINTED EARS I AM.
READY WHENEVER
YOU ARE, CAPTAIN.
ENERGIZE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
RED ALERT.
WHAT IS IT, CAPTAIN?
CESTUS 3
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
FULL ALERT.
TRICORDER READINGS,
MR. SPOCK.
LIFE DETECTION.
THOSE MESSAGES
WE GOT, CAPTAIN,
THE ONE DIRECTING US
HERE YESTERDAY...
FAKED. ALL THIS HAPPENED
SEVERAL DAYS AGO.
LANG, OVER THERE.
LOOK FOR SURVIVORS.
KELOWITZ, THAT WAY.
O'HERLIHY,
STICK WITH ME.
CAPTAIN, IMPULSES
THAT DIRECTION--
VERY WEAK,
POSSIBLY A SURVIVOR.
COME ON, BONES.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3045.6--
THE ENTERPRISE
HAS RESPONDED TO A CALL
FROM EARTH OBSERVATION
OUTPOST ON CESTUS 3.
ON LANDING,
WE HAVE DISCOVERED
THAT THE OUTPOST
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
CAPTAIN, OVER THERE.
CAREFUL. CAREFUL.
SHOCK, RADIATION BURNS,
INTERNAL INJURIES FOR CERTAIN.
HE'S IN A BAD WAY,
CAPTAIN.
KEEP HIM ALIVE,
BONES.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT'S BEEN
HAPPENING HERE.
GETTING ANOTHER
LIFE READING,
CAPTAIN.
SURVIVORS?
NOT SURVIVORS--
NOT WARMBLOODED.
LIVING CREATURES,
BUT NOT HUMAN.
WHERE?
AZIMUTH 93 DEGREES,
RANGE 1,570 YARDS.
O'HERLIHY.
CAPTAIN, I SEE SOMETHING.
[SHELL FALLS]
[EXPLOSION]
COVER!
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
LOCK ON TRANSPORTERS.
BEAM US UP.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE COMING UNDER ATTACK.
UNIDENTIFIED SHIP
QUARTERING IN.
WE CAN'T BEAM YOU UP.
I'VE JUST RIGGED UP
DEFENSIVE SCREENS.
KEEP THOSE SCREENS UP.
FIRE ALL PHASERS.
FIRING PHASERS, CAPTAIN.
ALIEN HAS SCREENS UP, TOO.
TAKE ALL ACTION NECESSARY
TO PROTECT THE SHIP.
WE'LL HOLD OUT HERE.
ARE YOU UNDER ATTACK,
CAPTAIN?
WE COULD DROP SCREENS.
KEEP THOSE SCREENS UP.
WORRY ABOUT US
WHEN THE SHIP IS SAFE.
KIRK OUT.
[SHELL FALLS]
[EXPLOSION]
IF THEY LOWER THOSE SCREENS
TO BEAM US UP,
THEY'LL BE OPEN
TO PHASER ATTACK.
WE'RE HOPELESSLY
OUTNUMBERED HERE,
CAPTAIN.
WITH THOSE
DISRUPTORS VERSUS
OUR HAND PHASERS...
WE'RE STUCK WITH IT,
MR. SPOCK.
WE'LL HAVE TO MAKE DO
WITH WHAT WE'VE GOT.
KELOWITZ, LANG,
FLANK OUT.
LAY DOWN FIRE
ON COORDINATES
MR. SPOCK GAVE YOU...
EVEN IF YOU DON'T
SEE 'EM.
KEEP YOUR HEADS DOWN.
[EXPLOSION]
HELPLESS DOWN HERE,
AND THE ENTERPRISE--
SULU'S AN EXPERIENCED
COMBAT OFFICER, CAPTAIN.
IT'S MY SHIP, MR. SPOCK.
I SHOULD BE THERE.
[EXPLOSION]
WE CAN'T EVEN
GET AT THEM.
NOR CAN THEY AT US
AT THE MOMENT,
NOT UNLESS
THEY MOVE THEIR
ORIGINAL POSITION
TO THAT INTERVENING
HIGH GROUND.
YOU REMEMBER THE LAYOUT
OF THIS PLACE, THE ARSENAL?
ABOUT 100 YARDS
IN THAT DIRECTION,
BUT AFTER AN ATTACK
AS THOROUGH
AS THIS ONE--
I'LL RISK IT.
[EXPLOSION]
[SHELL FALLS]
KIRK HERE. REPORT.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
NEVER MIND ABOUT ME.
WHAT ABOUT THE SHIP?
WE RETURNED FIRE
WITH ALL PHASER BANKS--
NEGATIVE AGAINST
THIS DEFLECTOR SCREEN.
ARM YOUR PHOTON TORPEDOES.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
ARM PHOTON TORPEDOES.
STAND BY.
ANY IDENTIFICATION
ON THE ATTACKING VESSEL?
NO, SIR.
DOESN'T CORRESPOND
WITH ANY CONFIGURATION
WE'RE FAMILIAR WITH.
WE CAN'T
GET VISUAL CONTACT.
SHE'S TOO FAR AWAY.
MR. SULU,
PHOTON TORPEDOES LOCKED ON.
PHOTON TORPEDOES
LOCKED ON, CAPTAIN.
FIRE ALL BANKS.
ALL BANKS FIRED,
SIR.
SULU--
[STATIC]
SULU, OUR COMMUNICATIONS
ARE BEING INTERFERED WITH.
[SHELL FALLS]
NOW GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU DO ANYTHING
YOU THINK NECESSARY
TO PROTECT THE SHIP--
LEAVE ORBIT, MAXIMUM WARP--
ANYTHING. CLEAR?
CLEAR, CAPTAIN,
BUT YOU--
NEVER MIND ABOUT ME.
PROTECT MY SHIP.
YES, SIR.
PHOTON TORPEDOES
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
I'M WARPING OUT
OF ORBIT.
GOOD. CONTACT ME
WHEN YOU CAN. KIRK OUT.
[BOMBARDMENT CONTINUING]
HOW IS HE, DOCTOR?
HE'LL BE DEAD
IN HALF AN HOUR
IF WE DON'T GET HIM
SOME DECENT CARE.
THEY'RE MOVING.
I'VE GOT TO GET
TO THE CAPTAIN.
[SHELL FALLS]
LOCKED ON
TO THE ENEMY, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE MOVING
TOWARD THE HIGH GROUND.
THEY'VE LOCKED ON
TO MY TRICORDER.
[EXPLOSION]
VERY INGENIOUS.
THEY FED BACK
MY OWN IMPULSES
AND BUILT UP
AN OVERLOAD.
WE'LL SEE
HOW INGENIOUS THEY ARE.
HERE. GIVE ME A HAND
WITH THIS GRENADE LAUNCHER.
LANG!
ANY WORD
FROM THE ENTERPRISE?
SULU'S TAKEN HER
OUT OF ORBIT.
THEY GOT LANG, SIR.
DID YOU SEE THEM?
NO, SIR.
AN EVALUATION,
MR. KELOWITZ.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
THEY ARE?
IF I WERE THEM,
I'D GO TO THE HIGH GROUND
ON THE RIGHT.
I'D MAKE IT 1,200 YARDS,
AZIMUTH 87.
IT'S PRETTY CLOSE
FOR, UH, ONE OF THESE
LITTLE JEWELS, CAPTAIN.
IT'LL BE A LOT CLOSER
TO THEM. STAND CLEAR.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
Sulu: CAPTAIN,
THE ALIEN'S WITHDRAWING.
SHE'S AT EXTREME RANGE,
BUT OUR SENSORS INDICATE
SHE JUST ACTIVATED
HER TRANSPORTERS.
LOCK ON TO THE ALIEN,
MR. SULU.
I DON'T WANT
TO LOSE HER.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
OUR SCREENS ARE DOWN.
WE CAN BEAM
YOU UP NOW, SIR.
I WANT A SEARCH PARTY
OF 30 MEDICAL PERSONNEL
BEAMED DOWN IMMEDIATELY
TO SEARCH FOR SURVIVORS.
NOTIFY THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
LOCK ONTO US.
WE'RE BEAMING UP.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENT.
WE HAVE BEAMED BACK
TO THE ENTERPRISE
AND IMMEDIATELY SET OUT
IN PURSUIT
OF THE ALIEN VESSEL.
IT APPEARS TO BE HEADED
TOWARDS A LARGELY UNEXPLORED
SECTION OF THE GALAXY.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT HAPPENED?
SCANNERS
REPORTED A SHIP
APPROACHING.
WE GET THEM
NOW AND THEN.
THEY'RE ALL
WELCOME TO USE
OUR FACILITIES.
YOU KNOW THAT.
YES, I KNOW.
THEY CAME IN
SPACE NORMAL SPEED,
USING OUR REGULAR
APPROACH ROUTE,
BUT...
THEY KNOCKED OUT
OUR PHASER BATTERIES
WITH THEIR
FIRST SALVO.
FROM THEN ON,
WE WERE HELPLESS.
WE WEREN'T
EXPECTING ANYTHING!
WHY SHOULD WE?!
WE DIDN'T HAVE
ANYTHING ANYONE
WOULD WANT!
EASY. EASY.
THEY POURED IT ON,
LIKE--LIKE PHASERS,
ONLY WORSE,
WHATEVER THEY
WERE USING.
I TR-TRIED
TO SIGNAL THEM.
WE CALLED UP,
TRIED TO SURRENDER.
WE HAD WOMEN
AND CHILDREN.
I TOLD THEM THAT.
I BEGGED THEM.
THEY WOULDN'T
LISTEN.
THEY DIDN'T LET UP
FOR A MOMENT.
LIEUTENANT, THE ENTERPRISE
RECEIVED 2 MESSAGES,
OSTENSIBLY
FROM CESTUS 3--
ONE FOR THE ENTERPRISE
TO GO THERE
AND THE OTHER FOR MYSELF
AND MY TACTICAL CREW
TO BEAM DOWN
TO THE SURFACE.
THEY HIT US A FULL DAY
BEFORE YOU GOT THERE,
CAPTAIN.
NO MESSAGES
CAME FROM US, CAPTAIN.
WHY DID THEY DO IT?
WHY?!
THERE HAS TO BE
A REASON.
THERE HAS
TO BE A REASON!
IT WAS A TRAP--
GETTING THE ENTERPRISE
TO COME TO CESTUS 3,
GETTING US AND OUR WHOLE CREW
TO COME ASHORE.
VERY CLEVER.
AS TO THE REASON...
THE REASON
IS CRYSTAL CLEAR.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS THE ONLY PROTECTION
IN THIS SECTION
OF THE FEDERATION.
DESTROY THE ENTERPRISE,
AND EVERYTHING
IS WIDE OPEN.
YOU ALLUDE TO INVASION,
CAPTAIN,
YET POSITIVE PROOF HAS--
I HAVE ALL THE PROOF
I NEED ON CESTUS 3.
NOT NECESSARILY, SIR.
SEVERAL POSSIBLE
EXPLANATIONS COME--
HOW CAN YOU EXPLAIN
A MASSACRE LIKE THAT?
NO, MR. SPOCK,
THE THREAT IS CLEAR
AND IMMEDIATE.
INVASION.
VERY WELL, THEN.
IF THAT'S THE CASE,
YOU MUST MAKE CERTAIN
THAT THE ALIEN VESSEL
NEVER REACHES
ITS HOME BASE.
I INTEND TO.
IF WE CAN KEEP THEM
IN THE DARK
AS TO OUR STRENGTH,
THEY'LL NEVER DARE
MOVE AGAINST US.
CAPTAIN TO HELMSMAN.
SULU HERE, SIR.
IS THE ALIEN STILL
MAKING WARP 5?
AFFIRMATIVE, SIR.
INITIATE WARP 6.
OVERTAKE.
PHASER BANKS...
LOCK ON
TO THE ENEMY VESSEL.
STAND BY
FOR FIRING ORDERS.
[SIREN BLARING]
ALL HANDS,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WE ARE GOING
INTO BATTLE.
ALL HANDS,
BATTLE STATIONS.
RED ALERT.
I REPEAT, RED ALERT.
THIS IS NO DRILL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3046.2--
WE ARE IN HOT PURSUIT
OF THE ALIEN VESSEL
WHICH DESTROYED
THE EARTH OUTPOST
ON CESTUS 3.
MR. DePAUL.
YES, SIR?
POSITION?
22.3 PARSECS BEYOND
LATEST CHART LIMIT, SIR.
ALL SCANNERS LOCK
INTO COMPUTER BANKS.
I WANT A COMPLETE
RECORD OF THIS.
SPOCK, WHAT DO WE HAVE
ON THIS GENERAL AREA?
VIRTUALLY NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
NO RECORDS
OF ANY EXPLORATIONS.
THERE ARE RUMORS OF
CERTAIN STRANGE SIGNALS
ON SUBSPACE CHANNELS.
HOWEVER, NONE HAS
EVER BEEN RECORDED.
ANYTHING ON
INTELLIGENT LIFE-FORMS?
NOTHING SPECIFIC, CAPTAIN.
UNSCIENTIFIC RUMORS ONLY.
MORE LIKE SPACE LEGENDS.
[INTERCOM]
SECURITY CONTROL TO BRIDGE.
STATUS REPORT--ALL DECKS...
MR. SULU, STATUS--
ALIEN VESSEL.
THEY MUST BE
AWARE WE'RE
AFTER THEM, SIR.
THEY'VE GONE
TO WARP 6 ALSO.
WARP FACTOR 7.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
SOMETHING THE MATTER,
MR. SPOCK?
A SUSTAINED WARP 7 SPEED
WILL BE DANGEROUS, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
I MEAN TO CATCH THEM.
WE'LL EITHER
CATCH THEM, OR WE'LL
BLOW UP, CAPTAIN.
THEY MAY BE FASTER
THAN WE ARE.
THEY'LL HAVE
TO PROVE IT.
YES, MR. SPOCK?
YOU MEAN TO DESTROY
THE ALIEN SHIP, CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE.
I THOUGHT PERHAPS
THE HOT PURSUIT ALONE
MIGHT BE SUFFICIENT.
DESTRUCTION MIGHT BE
UNNECESSARY.
COLONY CESTUS 3 HAS BEEN
OBLITERATED, MR. SPOCK.
THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE ALIEN VESSEL
WILL NOT HELP
THAT COLONY, JIM.
IF THE ALIENS
GO UNPUNISHED,
THEY'LL BE BACK,
ATTACKING OTHER
FEDERATION INSTALLATIONS.
I'M MERELY
SUGGEST THAT A REGARD
FOR SENTIENT LIFE--
THERE'S NO TIME FOR THAT.
IT'S A MATTER
OF POLICY.
OUT HERE,
WE'RE THE ONLY POLICEMEN AROUND,
AND A CRIME
HAS BEEN COMMITTED.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR?
VERY CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
I'M DELIGHTED, MR. SPOCK.
[INTERCOM]
MEDICAL SECTION TO BRIDGE.
WE NEED A CALL
FROM THE BRIDGE--
REPORT, MR. SULU.
ALIEN SHIP MAINTAINING,
INTERVAL, CAPTAIN.
NOW AT WARP 7.
[INDISTINCT
INTERCOM CHATTER]
[INTERCOM]
EMERGENCY, DECK 5.
...DECK 3.
EMERGENCY, DECK 3.
WARP FACTOR 8.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN
TO PHASER BANKS.
ALL COMPONENTS
AT BATTLE-READY.
ALL BANKS PRIMED.
[INTERCOM]
AFT PHASER TO BRIDGE.
ALERT STATUS. ALL WEAPONS
OPERATIONAL AND READY.
CAPTAIN.
YES, MR. SULU?
CLOSING ON TARGET,
SIR.
GOOD. MR. DePAUL.
YES, SIR.
OUR POSITION.
2279PL, SIR.
UNCHARTED SOLAR
SYSTEM AT 2466PM.
IS IT ON
THE ALIEN'S COURSE?
NO, SIR.
HE'S HEADED
AWAY FROM IT.
CAPTAIN, SENSORS REPORT
WE'RE BEING SCANNED.
BY THE ALIEN SHIP?
NO, SIR. IT'S FROM
THAT SOLAR SYSTEM AHEAD.
ANY INTERFERENCE,
RESISTANCE?
NO, SIR,
JUST SCANNING BEAMS.
IT'S ON
AN UNUSUAL WAVELENGTH.
MR. SPOCK.
IT WOULD APPEAR SOMEONE
IS CURIOUS ABOUT US.
MR. SULU.
IS THE ALIEN
STILL HEADING AWAY
FROM THAT SOLAR SYSTEM?
YES, SIR.
WE'RE CLOSING, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ANYTHING FURTHER
ON THOSE SCANNING BEAMS?
THERE'S NO
HOSTILITY, SIR.
THEY'RE NOT TRACTORS
OR WEAPONS OF ANY SORT,
JUST INCREASING
IN INTENSITY.
STEADY...
REGULAR...
IT'S GROWING
STRONGER, SIR.
CAPTAIN!
YES, WHAT IS IT?
THE ALIEN,
IT'S SLOWING DOWN.
WARP 5...4...
2.
IT'S GOING
SUBLIGHT, SIR.
SIR...
IT STOPPED
DEAD IN SPACE.
HE MAY BE
TURNING TO FIGHT.
NO, SIR.
THEY'RE JUST
DEAD OUT THERE.
ARE YOU SURE?
YES, SIR.
UNMOVING.
THEN WE'VE GOT HIM!
GO TO RED ALERT.
PREPARE TO FIRE
PHASER BANKS.
SENSORS, LOCK ON.
MR. SULU,
CONTINUE CLOSING.
MR. SPOCK...
LOCK PHASERS
INTO COMPUTER.
COMPUTERS WILL
CONTROL ATTACK.
COMPUTER LOCK READY,
CAPTAIN.
ALL SYSTEMS
STANDING BY.
RANGE IS 1810,
1760.
RANGE IS 1700,
1640.
RANGE IS 1590...
1550 AND CLOSING,
SIR.
[CRASH]
WARP 6...WARP 5...
4...WARP 3...
WARP 1.
SUBLIGHT, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE STOPPED,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE,
BUT--
[INTERCOM] A-G SECTION,
WE'RE READING ONLY
4.5 HERE. CONFIRM.
WE'RE HAVING IT
DOWN TO .8.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WARP 8. HAVE YOU
LOST YOUR MIND?
SAME AS THE ALIEN,
CAPTAIN.
[INTERCOM] ...ACKNOWLEDGING.
A-G SECTION ACKNOWLEDGING.
SECTION IS STABLE...
MR. SCOTT, REPORT.
WE'RE DEAD,
CAPTAIN, LOCKED UP,
FROZEN TIGHT.
ALL PROPULSION
SYSTEMS READ ZERO.
LIFE SYSTEMS?
THEY'RE ALL NORMAL,
SIR--
ATMOSPHERE,
HEAT, LIGHT--
NO VARIANCE.
PHASER BANKS.
REPORT.
[INTERCOM] WE'RE ALL
INOPERATIVE HERE, CAPTAIN.
NO POWER AT ALL.
NO FAULTY CIRCUITS
I CAN FIND.
JUST NO POWER.
DAMAGE CONTROL,
REPORT.
ALL SYSTEMS
REPORT NORMAL, CAPTAIN.
NO ASCERTAINABLE DAMAGE.
THEN WHAT IS IT?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR,
BUT WHATEVER IT IS,
WE CANNA MOVE.
WE'RE BEING HELD
IN PLACE, CAPTAIN,
APPARENTLY
FROM THAT SOLAR SYSTEM.
THIS FAR OUT?
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WE ARE BEING HELD.
TRACTOR BEAMS?
NO, SIR,
AN UNIDENTIFIABLE POWER.
WE ARE THE METRONS.
YOU ARE ONE OF 2 CRAFTS
WHICH HAVE COME
INTO OUR SPACE
ON A MISSION OF VIOLENCE.
THIS IS NOT PERMISSIBLE.
YET WE HAVE ANALYZED YOU
AND HAVE LEARNED
THAT YOUR VIOLENT TENDENCIES
ARE INHERENT.
SO BE IT.
WE WILL CONTROL THEM.
WE WILL RESOLVE
YOUR CONFLICT
IN THE WAY MOST SUITED
TO YOUR LIMITED MENTALITIES.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
THIS IS KIRK.
WE HAVE PREPARED
A PLANET
WITH A SUITABLE
ATMOSPHERE.
YOU WILL BE TAKEN THERE,
AS WILL THE CAPTAIN
OF THE GORN SHIP WHICH
YOU HAVE BEEN PURSUING.
THERE YOU WILL SETTLE
YOUR DISPUTE.
I...DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU WILL BE PROVIDED
WITH A RECORDING-TRANSLATING
DEVICE
IN HOPES THAT A CHRONICLE
OF THIS CONTEST
WILL SERVE TO DISSUADE
OTHERS OF YOUR KIND
FROM ENTERING OUR SYSTEM,
BUT YOU WILL
NOT BE PERMITTED
TO COMMUNICATE
WITH YOUR SHIP.
YOU WILL EACH
BE TOTALLY ALONE.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU CAN INTERFERE--
IT IS YOU
WHO ARE INTERFERING.
WE ARE SIMPLY
PUTTING A STOP TO IT.
THE PLACE WE HAVE
PREPARED FOR YOU
CONTAINS SUFFICIENT ELEMENTS
FOR EITHER OF YOU
TO CONSTRUCT WEAPONS
LETHAL ENOUGH
TO DESTROY THE OTHER,
WHICH SEEMS
TO BE YOUR INTENTION.
THE WINNER OF THE CONTEST
WILL BE PERMITTED
TO GO HIS WAY UNHARMED.
THE LOSER,
ALONG WITH HIS SHIP,
SHALL BE DESTROYED
IN THE INTERESTS OF PEACE.
THE CONTEST WILL BE ONE
OF INGENUITY AGAINST INGENUITY,
BRUTE STRENGTH
AGAINST BRUTE STRENGTH.
THE RESULTS
WILL BE FINAL.
JUST A MIN--
THERE WILL BE
NO DISCUSSION.
IT IS DONE.
AAH!
HE'S GONE.
[HISSING]
Kirk: THE ENTERPRISE
IS DEAD IN SPACE,
STOPPED COLD
DURING HER PURSUIT
OF AN ALIEN RAIDER
BY MYSTERIOUS FORCES,
AND I HAVE SOMEHOW BEEN
WHISKED OFF THE BRIDGE
AND PLACED ON THE SURFACE
OF AN ASTEROID,
FACING THE CAPTAIN
OF THE ALIEN SHIP.
WEAPONLESS, I FACE THE CREATURE
THE METRONS CALLED A GORN--
LARGE, REPTILIAN.
LIKE MOST HUMANS,
I SEEM TO HAVE AN INSTINCTIVE
REVULSION TO REPTILES.
I MUST FIGHT TO REMEMBER
THAT THIS IS AN INTELLIGENT,
HIGHLY ADVANCED INDIVIDUAL,
THE CAPTAIN OF A STARSHIP
LIKE MYSELF,
UNDOUBTEDLY A DANGEROUSLY
CLEVER OPPONENT.
[HISSING]
[ROARS]
[GROWLS]
[HISSING]
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
HAVE YOU TRIED OVERLOAD?
AYE, SIR.
IT DOES NO GOOD.
HOW ABOUT BYPASSING
THE TRANSFORMER BANKS,
FEED THE IMPULSE ENGINES
DIRECTLY?
I TRIED THAT, SIR.
NOTHING.
[INTERCOM] SECURITY
CONTROL TO BRIDGE.
STATUS REPORT--ALL DECKS
REPORTING GREEN AND...
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HAVE SENSORS LEARNED
ANYTHING ABOUT
THE NATURE OF THE FORCE
WHICH HOLDS US HERE?
NO, SIR. THEY REPORT
THEY DEFINITELY EMANATE FROM
THAT SOLAR SYSTEM AHEAD.
NO INDICATION
OF ITS COMPOSITION?
GRAVIMETRIC, MAGNETIC,
ELECTRONIC?
NOTHING, SIR.
THIS IS
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
WHOEVER FINDS THIS...
PLEASE GET IT
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
I'M ENGAGED
IN PERSONAL COMBAT
WITH A CREATURE
APPARENTLY CALLED A GORN.
HE'S IMMENSELY STRONG.
ALREADY HE HAS WITHSTOOD
ATTACKS FROM ME
THAT WOULD HAVE KILLED
A HUMAN BEING.
FORTUNATELY,
THOUGH STRONG,
HE'S NOT AGILE.
THE AGILITY
AND, I HOPE,
THE CLEVERNESS
IS MINE.
THE METRONS--
THE CREATURES
THAT SENT US BOTH HERE...
SAID THAT THE SURFACE
OF THE PLANET
PROVIDES THE RAW MATERIAL...
TO CONSTRUCT...
WEAPONS.
THERE'S VERY LITTLE HERE--
SCRUB BRUSH, ROCKS,
AN ABUNDANCE
OF MINERAL DEPOSITS,
BUT NO WEAPONS
IN THE CONVENTIONAL SENSE.
STILL,
I NEED TO FIND ONE.
BAREHANDED...
AGAINST THE GORN...
I HAVE NO CHANCE.
[INTERCOM] MEDICAL
SECTION TO THE BRIDGE...
LEAVE CHANNEL ONE OPEN,
LIEUTENANT, JUST IN CASE.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO, MR. SPOCK?
I'M GOING TO WAIT,
DOCTOR.
THERE IS LITTLE ELSE
I CAN DO.
WHAT ABOUT THE CAPTAIN?
IF I COULD HELP HIM,
I WOULD.
I CANNOT.
NOW, YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT'S ALWAYS TALKING
ABOUT LOGIC.
WHAT ABOUT
SOME LOGIC NOW?
WHERE'S THE CAPTAIN,
MR. SPOCK?
HE'S OUT THERE, DOCTOR,
OUT THERE SOMEWHERE
IN A THOUSAND
CUBIC PARSECS OF SPACE,
AND THERE'S ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING WE CAN DO TO HELP HIM.
A LARGE DEPOSIT
OF DIAMONDS
ON THE SURFACE--
PERHAPS
THE HARDEST SUBSTANCE
KNOWN IN THE UNIVERSE,
BEAUTIFULLY CRYSTALLIZED
AND POINTED,
BUT TOO SMALL TO BE
USEFUL AS A WEAPON.
AN INCREDIBLE FORTUNE
IN STONES...
YET I WOULD
TRADE THEM ALL
FOR A HAND PHASER
OR A GOOD SOLID CLUB.
YET THE METRONS SAID
THERE WOULD BE WEAPONS...
IF I COULD FIND THEM.
WHERE?
[GORN SNARLS]
WHAT KIND?
[GROWL]
[PEBBLES CLATTER]
[CHUCKLES]
[GORN YELLS]
[HISSING]
OHH! [GROANING]
[GORN GROWLS]
[HISSING]
[ROARS]
THIS IS THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
CALLING THE METRONS.
OUR CHANNELS ARE OPEN.
COME IN, PLEASE.
WE URGENTLY DESIRE
A CONFERENCE.
PLEASE ANSWER.
THIS MAY BE
MY LAST ENTRY.
I AM ALMOST EXHAUSTED.
UNLESS I FIND THE WEAPON
THE METRON MENTIONED...
I HAVE
VERY LITTLE TIME LEFT.
NATIVE SULFUR, DIAMONDS.
THIS PLACE IS
A MINERALOGIST'S DREAM.
YET...
THERE IS SOMETHING...
ABOUT SULFUR.
SOMETHING VERY OLD.
SOMETHING--
[GROWL]
IF ONLY I COULD REMEMBER.
THE SHIP, OUR ENGINES,
OUR WEAPONS...
IT'S JUST INCONCEIVABLE
THAT WE ARE IMMOBILIZED.
MMM.
BUT IT HAS HAPPENED,
DOCTOR.
WE ARE THE METRONS.
YOUR CAPTAIN
IS LOSING HIS BATTLE.
WE WOULD SUGGEST YOU MAKE
WHATEVER MEMORIAL
ARRANGEMENTS, IF ANY,
WHICH ARE CUSTOMARY
IN YOUR CULTURE.
WE BELIEVE YOU HAVE
VERY LITTLE TIME LEFT.
WE APPEAL TO YOU
IN THE NAME OF
CIVILIZATION.
PUT A STOP TO THIS.
YOUR VIOLENT INTENT
AND ACTIONS
DEMONSTRATE
THAT YOU ARE NOT CIVILIZED.
HOWEVER, WE ARE NOT
WITHOUT COMPASSION.
IT IS POSSIBLE
YOU MAY HAVE FEELINGS
TOWARD YOUR CAPTAIN.
SO THAT YOU WILL BE ABLE
TO PREPARE YOURSELF,
WE WILL ALLOW YOU
TO SEE AND HEAR
WHAT IS NOW TRANSPIRING.
[GORN HISSING]
IF THERE WERE ONLY SOME WAY
WE COULD CONTACT HIM.
YES, INDEED, DOCTOR,
IF ONLY THERE WERE.
NOTICE THE SUBSTANCE
INCRUSTING THAT ROCK.
YES.
UNLESS I'M MISTAKEN,
IT'S POTASSIUM NITRATE.
SO?
PERHAPS NOTHING,
DOCTOR.
PERHAPS EVERYTHING.
EARTHLING!
CAPTAIN!
WHO IS THIS,
THE METRON?
THIS IS YOUR OPPONENT,
EARTHLING.
I HAVE HEARD EVERY WORD
YOU HAVE SAID.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I WEARY OF THE CHASE.
WAIT FOR ME.
I SHALL BE MERCIFUL
AND QUICK.
LIKE YOU WERE
AT CESTUS 3?
YOU WERE INTRUDING!
YOU ESTABLISHED
AN OUTPOST
IN OUR SPACE.
YOU BUTCHERED
HELPLESS HUMAN BEINGS--
WE DESTROYED INVADERS,
AS I SHALL DESTROY YOU!
CAN THAT BE TRUE?
WAS CESTUS 3
AN INTRUSION
ON THEIR SPACE?
IT MAY WELL BE POSSIBLE,
DOCTOR.
WE KNOW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT THAT SECTION
OF THE GALAXY.
THEN WE COULD BE
IN THE WRONG.
PERHAPS.
THAT IS SOMETHING
BEST DECIDED BY DIPLOMATS.
THE GORNS SIMPLY
MIGHT HAVE BEEN TRYING
TO PROTECT THEMSELVES.
YES.
[GORN GROWLING]
FASCINATING.
GOOD.
HE KNOWS, DOCTOR.
HE HAS REASONED IT OUT.
[GORN HISSING]
Spock: YES.
YES.
WHAT IS IT, SPOCK?
AN INVENTION, DOCTOR.
FIRST POTASSIUM NITRATE,
AND NOW IF HE CAN
FIND SOME SULFUR
AND A CHARCOAL DEPOSIT
OR ORDINARY COAL...
McCoy: WHAT'S HE DOING?
DIAMONDS, THE HARDEST
KNOWN SUBSTANCE.
IMPELLED BY
SUFFICIENT FORCE,
THEY WOULD MAKE
FORMIDABLE PROJECTILES.
WHAT FORCE?
RECALL YOUR
BASIC CHEMISTRY, DOCTOR.
GUNPOWDER.
CAPTAIN, LET US
BE REASONABLE.
YOU HAVE LOST.
ADMIT IT
TO YOURSELF.
STOP RUNNING.
COAL.
CAN HE DO IT?
IF HE HAS THE TIME,
DOCTOR.
IF HE HAS THE TIME.
[HISSING]
NO.
NO, I WON'T KILL YOU.
MAYBE YOU THOUGHT
YOU WERE...
PROTECTING YOURSELF...
WHEN YOU
ATTACKED THE OUTPOST.
NO, I WON'T KILL HIM!
DO YOU HEAR?
YOU'LL HAVE TO GET
YOUR ENTERTAINMENT
SOMEPLACE ELSE!
YOU'RE A METRON?
DOES MY APPEARANCE
SURPRISE YOU, CAPTAIN?
YOU SEEM
MORE LIKE A BOY.
I AM APPROXIMATELY
1,500 OF YOUR
EARTH-YEARS OLD.
YOU SURPRISE ME,
CAPTAIN.
HOW?
BY SPARING
YOUR HELPLESS ENEMY
WHO SURELY WOULD
HAVE DESTROYED YOU,
YOU DEMONSTRATED
THE ADVANCED
TRAIT OF MERCY,
SOMETHING
WE HARDLY EXPECTED.
WE FEEL THERE MAY BE
HOPE FOR YOUR KIND.
THEREFORE YOU WILL
NOT BE DESTROYED.
IT WOULD NOT BE...
CIVILIZED.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE GORN?
I SENT HIM
BACK TO HIS SHIP.
IF YOU LIKE,
I SHALL DESTROY HIM
FOR YOU.
NO. THAT WON'T
BE NECESSARY.
WE CAN TALK...
MAYBE...
REACH AN AGREEMENT.
VERY GOOD, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS HOPE FOR YOU.
PERHAPS IN
SEVERAL THOUSAND YEARS,
YOUR PEOPLE AND MINE
SHALL MEET
TO REACH AN AGREEMENT.
YOU ARE
STILL HALF SAVAGE,
BUT THERE IS HOPE.
WE WILL CONTACT YOU
WHEN WE ARE READY.
Uhura: CAPTAIN!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY.
BACK TO YOUR POSTS.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
CAPTAIN.
MR. SULU.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE, BUT...
THERE'S SIRIUS
OVER THERE WHEN IT
SHOULD BE HERE.
AND CANOPUS...
AND ARCANIS.
WE'RE--
ALL OF A SUDDEN, WE'RE
CLEAR ACROSS THE GALAXY,
500 PARSECS FROM WHERE
WE ARE--I MEAN, WERE.
I MEAN...
DON'T TRY AND
FIGURE IT OUT, MR. SULU.
JUST PLOT A COURSE
FOR US BACK TO CESTUS 3.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
AFTER YOU TOUCHED OFF
YOUR PRIMITIVE CANNON, CAPTAIN,
WE LOST THE PICTURE
THE METRON WAS SENDING US.
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED
DOWN THERE?
MOST OF IT.
I WOULD BE
INTERESTED IN KNOWING
WHAT FINALLY HAPPENED.
WE'RE A MOST PROMISING
SPECIES, MR. SPOCK...
AS PREDATORS GO.
DID YOU KNOW THAT?
I FREQUENTLY
HAD MY DOUBTS.
I DON'T.
NOT ANYMORE.
AND MAYBE IN
A THOUSAND YEARS OR SO,
WE'LL BE ABLE
TO PROVE IT.
NEVER MIND, MR. SPOCK.
IT DOESN'T MAKE
MUCH SENSE TO ME EITHER.
TAKE US BACK
TO WHERE WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE, MR. SULU.
WARP FACTOR 1.
A THOUSAND YEARS,
CAPTAIN?
WELL, THAT GIVES US
A LITTLE TIME.