CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT, WEBB?
A BLIP, SIR. JUST
CAME ON THE SCREEN.
HOW DO YOU READ IT?
AIRCRAFT OF SOME SORT.
BY THE SIZE OF IT
AND THE SPEED,
IT'S NOT
ONE OF OURS, SIR.
IT DOESN'T EVEN READ LIKE
ANYTHING I'VE EVER SEEN.
WHAT WAS THE APPROACH?
NONE, SIR. IT WAS
JUST THERE, LIKE IT
FELL OUT OF THE SKY
OR SOMETHING.
CURRENT POSITION?
DIRECTLY OVER THE OMAHA
INSTALLATION, SIR.
HOLDING THERE.
WATCH THE SCOPE, WEBB.
AIR DEFENSE WILL WANT
TO SEND SOMEBODY UP
TO GET A CLOSER LOOK.
I THINK WE HAVE A REAL
UFO ON OUR HANDS.
[ALARM BLARES]
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE
THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3113.2.
WE WERE EN ROUTE TO
STARBASE 9 FOR RESUPPLY
WHEN A BLACK STAR OF
HIGH-GRAVITATIONAL ATTRACTION
BEGAN TO DRAG US
TOWARD IT.
IT REQUIRED ALL
WARP POWER IN REVERSE
TO PULL US AWAY
FROM THE STAR.
BUT, LIKE
SNAPPING A RUBBER BAND,
THE BREAKAWAY SENT US
PLUNGING THROUGH SPACE,
OUT OF CONTROL,
TO STOP HERE...
WHEREVER WE ARE.
MR. SPOCK.
EXCEPT FOR
SECONDARY SYSTEMS,
EVERYTHING IS OUT, SIR.
WE'RE ON
IMPULSE POWER ONLY.
AUXILIARIES.
IF MR. SCOTT IS STILL
WITH IS,
THE AUXILIARIES SHOULD
BE ON MOMENTARILY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
LIEUTENANT?
IF MR. SCOTT IS
STILL WITH US.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
DAMAGE CONTROL PARTIES
ON ALL DECKS, CHECK IN.
ALL DEPARTMENTS, TIE-IN
WITH THE RECORD COMPUTER.
REPORT CASUALTIES
AND OPERATIONAL READINESS
TO THE FIRST OFFICER.
KIRK OUT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTACT
STARFLEET CONTROL.
I WANT THEM ALERTED
TO THE POSITION
OF THAT BLACK STAR
THAT'S IN THE AREA
OF STARBASE 9.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
CASUALTY REPORTS INDICATE
ONLY MINOR INJURIES.
ENGINEERING REPORTS
WARP ENGINES
NON-OPERATIONAL.
MR. SCOTT OVERRODE
THE AUTOMATIC HELM SETTING
AND IS HOLDING US IN ORBIT
ON IMPULSE POWER.
ORBIT WHERE, MR. SPOCK?
EARTH, CAPTAIN.
WE WERE ON A GENERAL
COURSE IN THIS DIRECTION
WHEN WE WERE PULLED
IN BY THE STAR.
APPARENTLY,
THE BREAKAWAY THREW US
ON IN THE SAME DIRECTION.
SCREEN ON.
WE ARE TOO LOW
IN THE ATMOSPHERE TO
RETAIN THIS ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
ENGINEERING REPORTS
WE HAVE SUFFICIENT
IMPULSE POWER
TO ACHIEVE
ESCAPE VELOCITY.
GIVE US SOME
ALTITUDE, MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.
HELM ANSWERING.
SHE'S SLUGGISH, SIR.
CAPTAIN,
NORMAL STARFLEET
CHANNEL HAS NOTHING
ON IT BUT STATIC.
I'M GETTING SOMETHING
ON ANOTHER FREQUENCY,
BUT IT'S NOT STARFLEET.
PUT IT ON AUDIO.
Man: THIS IS THE 5:30
NEWS SUMMARY.
CAPE KENNEDY--THE FIRST
MANNED MOON SHOT
IS SCHEDULED FOR
WEDNESDAY, 6 A.M.,
EASTERN STANDARD TIME.
ALL THREE ASTRONAUTS
WHO ARE TO MAKE THIS
HISTORIC--
MANNED MOON SHOT?
THAT WAS IN
THE LATE 1960s.
APPARENTLY, CAPTAIN,
SO ARE WE.
WHAT?
THE WHIPLASH PROPELLED
US INTO A TIME WARP,
CAPTAIN.
BACKWARD. EXACT
CHRONOMETER READINGS
IN A FEW MOMENTS.
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING
GROUND TO AIR TRANSMISSION.
Spock: VERIFIED.
SCANNERS REPORT SOME
TYPE OF CRAFT
APPROACHING
FROM BELOW US--
UNDER CLOUD COVER
AND CLOSING.
Man on radio: BLUEJAY 4,
THIS IS BLACKJACK.
WE'RE TRACKING BOTH
YOU AND THE UFO.
I HAVE HIM ON
MY SCREEN. FOLLOWING.
MR. SULU,
CAN YOU GAIN
ALTITUDE FASTER?
I WANT TO
OUTDISTANCE HIM.
PICKING UP, SIR. SHE'S
JUST SLOW IN RESPONDING.
BLACKJACK,
THIS IS BLUEJAY 4,
UFO IS PICKING UP
SPEED AND CLIMBING.
I'M GOING IN CLOSER.
Man on radio: BLUEJAY 4,
YOU SHOULD BE CLOSE ENOUGH
FOR VISUAL CONTACT.
I CAN SEE IT NOW.
WHATEVER THIS THING
IS, IT'S BIG.
TWO CYLINDRICAL
PROJECTIONS ON TOP,
ONE BELOW.
PURPOSE
UNDETERMINED.
WE HAVE TWO FLIGHTS
SCRAMBLED AND ON THE WAY.
THEY SHOULD RENDEZVOUS IN
YOUR SECTOR IN TWO MINUTES.
IT WON'T BE HERE.
THE UFO IS CLIMBING
AWAY FAST.
BLUEJAY 4,
YOU ARE ORDERED
TO CLOSE ON THE UFO
AND ATTEMPT TO FORCE
HIM TO LAND.
WE WANT IT BROUGHT DOWN
OR AT LEAST DISABLED UNTIL
THE OTHER PLANES ARRIVE.
Bluejay 4:
ACKNOWLEDGED.
CLOSING ON TARGET.
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION,
CAPTAIN.
AIRCRAFT IS
AN INTERCEPTOR,
EQUIPPED WITH MISSILES
AND POSSIBLY ARMED WITH
NUCLEAR WARHEADS.
IF HE HITS US
WITH ONE, HE MIGHT
DAMAGE US SEVERELY,
PERHAPS BEYOND OUR
CAPACITY TO REPAIR UNDER
CURRENT CIRCUMSTANCES.
SCOTTY,
ACTIVATE TRACTOR BEAM.
LOCK ON TO THAT AIRCRAFT
AND HOLD IT OUT THERE.
CAPTAIN, THIS
TYPE OF AIRCRAFT
MIGHT BE TOO FRAGILE
TO TAKE OUR TRACTOR BEAM.
Scotty: TRACTOR BEAM
ON, SIR.
WE HAVE THE TARGET.
AIRCRAFT IS
BREAKING UP, CAPTAIN.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
CAN YOU LOCK ON TO
THE COCKPIT OF THAT AIRCRAFT?
SCANNING AREA, SIR.
TRY AND BEAM
THAT PILOT ABOARD.
TAKE OVER, MR. SPOCK.
WELCOME ABOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN STEP OFF
THE TRANSPORTER,
UH--
CAPTAIN JOHN CHRISTOPHER,
UNITED STATES AIR FORCE.
SERIAL NUMBER 4857932.
RELAX, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE AMONG FRIENDS.
I'M CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
WHERE AM I?
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU PEOPLE--
WHO ARE YOU?
ALL IN GOOD TIME,
CAPTAIN.
MEANWHILE...
LET ME APOLOGIZE
FOR BRINGING YOU ABOARD
THIS SHIP SO ABRUPTLY.
BUT IT COULDN'T
BE HELPED.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT
YOUR CRAFT COULDN'T STAND UP
TO OUR TRACTOR BEAM.
DON'T GIVE ME
ANY DOUBLETALK.
JUST TELL ME WHO
YOU ARE.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT
WE DECIDE TO TELL YOU
IN A FEW MOMENTS.
IN THE MEANTIME, RELAX.
YOU'RE OUR GUEST.
I HAVE A FEELING
YOU'LL FIND IT INTERESTING.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
BRIDGE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE. WHAT IS IT,
MR. SPOCK?
THE AIRCRAFT HAS COMPLETELY
BROKEN UP, CAPTAIN.
SHALL WE TURN OFF
THE TRACTOR BEAM?
AFFIRMATIVE. WE
HAVE THE PILOT ABOARD.
I'LL BE RIGHT UP.
KIRK OUT.
FOLLOW ME.
GOOD MORNING, CAPTAIN.
GOOD MORNING.
CAPTAIN?
A WOMAN?
A CREWMAN.
BRIDGE.
MUST HAVE
TAKEN QUITE A LOT
TO BUILD A SHIP
LIKE THIS.
THERE ARE
ONLY 12 LIKE IT
IN THE FLEET.
I SEE.
DID THE NAVY--
WE'RE A COMBINED
SERVICE, CAPTAIN.
OUR AUTHORITY IS
THE UNITED EARTH
SPACE PROBE AGENCY.
UNITED EARTH?
THIS IS VERY
DIFFICULT TO EXPLAIN.
WE'RE FROM YOUR FUTURE.
A TIME WARP
PLACED US HERE.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
YOU SEEM TO
HAVE A LOT OF THEM.
HOWEVER...
I CAN'T DENY THE FACT
THAT YOU ARE HERE,
WITH THIS SHIP.
I NEVER HAVE BELIEVED
IN LITTLE GREEN MEN.
NEITHER HAVE I.
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER,
THIS IS MY
FIRST OFFICER,
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
SPOCK.
CAPTAIN.
FEEL FREE TO
LOOK AROUND, CAPTAIN.
DON'T TOUCH ANYTHING.
BUT I THINK YOU'LL
FIND IT INTERESTING.
INTERESTING IS
A WORD AND A HALF
FOR IT, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE ACHIEVED
A STABLE ORBIT OUT
OF EARTH'S ATMOSPHERE.
OUR DEFLECTORS
ARE OPERATIVE,
ENOUGH TO PREVENT OUR
BEING PICKED UP AGAIN
AS A UFO.
AND MR. SCOTT WISHES
TO SPEAK TO YOU
ABOUT THE ENGINES.
VERY WELL, MR. SPOCK--
ANYTHING ELSE
ON YOUR MIND?
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER.
WHAT ABOUT HIM?
WE CANNOT RETURN HIM
TO EARTH, CAPTAIN.
HE ALREADY KNOWS
TOO MUCH ABOUT US
AND IS LEARNING MORE.
I DO NOT
SPECIFICALLY REFER
TO CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER,
BUT SUPPOSE
AN UNSCRUPULOUS MAN
WERE TO GAIN
CERTAIN KNOWLEDGE
OF MAN'S FUTURE?
SUCH A MAN
COULD MANIPULATE
KEY INDUSTRIES,
STOCKS,
AND EVEN NATIONS.
AND, IN SO DOING,
CHANGE WHAT MUST BE.
AND IF IT
IS CHANGED, CAPTAIN,
YOU AND I, AND
ALL THAT WE KNOW,
MIGHT NOT EVEN EXIST.
YOUR LOGIC
CAN BE MOST...
ANNOYING.
THAT FLIGHT SUIT
MUST BE UNCOMFORTABLE.
WHY DON'T YOU HAVE
THE QUARTERMASTER
ISSUE HIM SOMETHING
MORE SUITABLE?
AND THEN I'LL WANT TO
MEET YOU AND HIM
IN MY QUARTERS.
YES, SIR.
COMPUTER ON. RECORD.
Computer:
RECORDING.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
COME.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
SUPPLEMENTAL.
ENGINEERING OFFICER SCOTT
INFORMS WARP ENGINES DAMAGED,
BUT CAN BE MADE OPERATIONAL
AND RE-ENERGIZED.
Computer: COMPUTED
AND RECORDED, DEAR.
COMPUTER, YOU WILL
NOT ADDRESS ME IN
THAT MANNER. COMPUTE.
COMPUTED, DEAR.
MR. SPOCK,
I ORDERED THIS COMPUTER
AND ITS INTERLINKING
SYSTEMS REPAIRED.
I HAVE INVESTIGATED
IT, CAPTAIN.
TO CORRECT THE FAULT
WILL REQUIRE
AN OVERHAUL OF THE ENTIRE
COMPUTER SYSTEM
AND A MINIMUM OF THREE WEEKS
AT A STARBASE.
I WOULDN'T MIND SO MUCH
IF ONLY IT DIDN'T GET SO...
AFFECTIONATE.
IT ALSO HAS AN UNFORTUNATE
TENDENCY TO GIGGLE.
[CHRISTOPHER CHUCKLES]
I TAKE IT THAT
A LADY COMPUTER
IS NOT ROUTINE.
WE'D PUT IT INTO SIGNET 14
FOR GENERAL REPAIR
AND MAINTENANCE.
SIGNET 14 IS A PLANET
DOMINATED BY WOMEN.
THEY SEEMED TO FEEL
THE SHIP'S COMPUTER SYSTEM
LACKED A PERSONALITY.
THEY GAVE IT ONE.
FEMALE, OF COURSE.
HA HA!
WELL, YOU PEOPLE
CERTAINLY HAVE
INTERESTING PROBLEMS.
I'D LOVE TO
STAY AROUND TO SEE
HOW YOUR GIRLFRIEND
WORKS OUT, BUT--
I'M AFRAID YOU'LL HAVE TO.
WE CAN'T SEND YOU BACK.
CAN'T?
WELL, SPOCK HERE TOLD ME
THAT YOUR TRANSPORTER
CAN BEAM DOWN AN OBJECT,
EVEN FROM
AN ORBIT THIS HIGH.
IT'S NOT THE TRANSPORTER.
IT'S YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THE FUTURE LOOKS LIKE.
IF ANYBODY
ELSE FINDS OUT,
THEY COULD CHANGE
THE COURSE OF IT
AND DESTROY IT.
WELL, THEN MY
DISAPPEARANCE WOULD
CHANGE SOMETHING, TOO.
I HAVE RUN A COMPUTER CHECK
ON ALL HISTORICAL TAPES.
THEY SHOW NO RECORD OF
ANY RELEVANT CONTRIBUTION
BY JOHN CHRISTOPHER.
LOOK, CAPTAIN,
I DON'T BUY ALL OF YOUR
TIME-ACCIDENT STORY.
NOW, THE EXPERTS CAN
FIGURE OUT WHO YOU ARE,
WHAT YOU ARE.
IT'S MY DUTY TO
REPORT WHAT I'VE SEEN.
WELL, WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
I'D...REPORT,
IF I COULD.
WE CAN'T
TAKE THE RISK.
I DON'T WANT TO
KNOW ABOUT RISKS.
I HAVE A WIFE,
TWO CHILDREN.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
I'M SORRY.
Scotty on intercom:
ENGINE ROOM
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT, SCOTTY?
PROGRESS REPORT, SIR.
EVERYTHING'S JERRY-RIGGED,
BUT WE'RE COMING ALONG
WITH THE REPAIRS.
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO RE-ENERGIZE IN
ABOUT FOUR HOURS, BUT, UH...
BUT WHAT, SCOTTY?
WELL, SIR, AS I SAY,
THE, UH, THE ENGINES
ARE BEING REPAIRED,
BUT WE'VE NO PLACE
TO GO IN THIS TIME.
IF YOU--
IF--IF YOU
SEE WHAT I MEAN?
SIR?
YES, SCOTTY, CARRY ON.
TOO BAD, CAPTAIN.
MAYBE I CAN'T GO HOME,
BUT NEITHER CAN YOU.
YOU'RE AS MUCH
A PRISONER
IN TIME AS I AM.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG
STARDATE 3113.7.
OUR ENGINES
ARE BEING REPAIRED,
BUT WE ARE STILL
LOCKED IN TIME.
AND WE HAVE ABOARD
A PASSENGER WHOM
WE DO NOT WANT,
AND WE CANNOT RETURN.
Computer:
RECOMMENDATION FOR
HIS DISPOSITION, DEAR.
MAINTENANCE NOTE--
MY RECORDING COMPUTER
HAS A SERIOUS MALFUNCTION.
RECOMMEND IT EITHER
BE CORRECTED...
OR SCRAPPED. COMPUTE.
[HESITANTLY]
COMPUTED.
Spock on intercom:
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK, HERE.
HAVE SOME NEW
INFORMATION REGARDING
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER.
IMPORTANT I SEE YOU
BOTH IMMEDIATELY.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
REPORT TO MY QUARTERS.
I'LL CONTACT
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER.
YES, SIR. BRIDGE OUT.
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER...
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER?
SECURITY, THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN.
SECURITY TEAM
HERE, SIR.
ALL-DECKS ALERT.
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
IS NOT IN HIS
ASSIGNED QUARTERS.
HE MAY BE TRYING
TO ESCAPE THE SHIP.
I WANT A MAN OUTSIDE
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
IMMEDIATELY.
I'M HEADING THERE MYSELF.
ALL RIGHT!
NICE AND EASY.
NOW I'M GOING TO STEP
INTO THAT THING,
AND YOU'RE GOING
TO TRANSPORT ME
BACK TO EARTH.
WELL, JIM, WITH
THE EXCEPTION OF
A SLIGHT BRUISE OR TWO,
OUR CAPTAIN IS
AS HEALTHY AS
A PROVERBIAL HORSE.
HE'LL BE COMING OUT OF
IT IN A MINUTE OR TWO.
HE TRIED TO ESCAPE.
I KNOW HOW HE FEELS,
BUT I CAN'T SEND HIM BACK
WITH WHAT HE KNOWS.
JIM, WHAT IF
WE CAN'T GO BACK?
WHAT CAN WE DO?
SIT UP HERE
AND WAIT FOR OUR
SUPPLIES TO RUN OUT,
OUR POWER TO DIE?
IT HAS TO EVENTUALLY,
AND WE CERTAINLY
CAN'T GO BACK TO EARTH.
IT WOULD BE WORSE
THAN THE CAPTAIN
BEING RETURNED.
THERE ARE 430 OF US.
NOW, THAT MEANS
430 CHANCES OF
ALTERING THE FUTURE.
YES. BUT WE'RE NOT
IN THAT POSITION YET.
WELL, I'M GLAD
TO HEAR IT.
AND IF WE DO GET BACK
TO WHERE WE BELONG,
THEN HE WON'T BELONG.
WE'RE ROUGHLY ABOUT
THE SAME AGE.
BUT IN OUR SOCIETY,
HE'D BE USELESS.
ARCHAIC.
BUT MAYBE HE COULD
BE RETRAINED,
REEDUCATED.
NOW YOU'RE
SOUNDING LIKE SPOCK.
WELL, IF YOU'RE
GONNA GET NASTY,
I'M GONNA LEAVE.
COULD HE BE RETRAINED
TO FORGET HIS FAMILY?
HIS CHILDREN?
THE ANSWER
TO THAT IS NO.
OH.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. I SEE PHYSICAL
TRAINING
IS REQUIRED IN
YOUR SERVICE, TOO.
HMM. CRUDE METHODS,
BUT EFFECTIVE.
WHAT DOES HE
MEAN BY THAT?
IT WAS JUST A JOKE, CAPTAIN.
YOU SAID YOU HAD
SOME ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION, MR. SPOCK?
I MADE AN ERROR
IN MY COMPUTATIONS.
OH? THIS COULD BE
AN HISTORIC OCCASION.
I FIND THAT WE MUST RETURN
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
TO EARTH AFTER ALL.
WHY? YOU SAID
I MADE NO RELATIVE
CONTRIBUTION.
POOR CHOICE OF WORDS
ON MY PART.
I NEGLECTED, IN MY
INITIAL RUN-THROUGH,
TO CORRELATE THE POSSIBLE
CONTRIBUTIONS BY OFFSPRING.
I FIND, AFTER RUNNING
A CROSS-CHECK
ON THAT FACTOR,
THAT YOUR SON, COLONEL
SEAN JEFFREY CHRISTOPHER,
HEADED, OR WILL HEAD,
THE FIRST SUCCESSFUL
EARTH-SATURN PROBE,
WHICH IS
A RATHER SIGNIFICANT--
WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T HAVE A SON.
YOU MEAN YET.
THE DOCTOR IS CORRECT.
UNLESS WE RETURN
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
TO EARTH,
THERE WILL BE NO COLONEL
SEAN JEFFREY CHRISTOPHER
TO GO TO SATURN.
WELL, THAT'S IT,
ISN'T IT?
WE'LL HAVE TO
FIND SOME WAY OF--
A BOY.
I'M GOING
TO HAVE A SON.
ACKNOWLEDGING THAT
WE MUST RETURN
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER,
THERE ARE
SEVERAL PROBLEMS,
PRIME OF WHICH IS
THE EXPLANATION
OF HIS RETURN.
WE TRACKED HIS
PLANE WRECKAGE DOWN
AFTER OUR TRACTOR BEAM
CRUSHED IT.
IT CRASHED
IN AN OPEN SECTION
OF SOUTHERN NEBRASKA.
THAT MEANS THOSE
SEARCH PARTIES
WILL BE CRAWLING
ALL OVER THAT WRECKAGE.
AND CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
HIMSELF COMPLICATED
THE MATTER.
WHEN I MADE
VISUAL CONTACT,
I TURNED ON
MY WING CAMERAS.
AND I GOT CLOSE ENOUGH
TO TAKE SOME PRETTY
CLEAR PICTURES OF YOU.
AIR DEFENSE COMMAND
WILL BE PROCESSING
THAT FILM FAST
AND ADC CONTROL WAS
PROBABLY RECORDING
MY RADIO TRANSMISSIONS.
IF I REMEMBER MY HISTORY,
THESE THINGS WERE
BEING DISMISSED AS
WEATHER BALLOONS,
SUN DOGS,
EXPLAINABLE THINGS,
AT LEAST PUBLICLY.
CAPTAIN, OUR TRACTOR BEAM
CAUGHT AND CRUSHED
AN AIR FORCE PLANE.
IT'LL BE IMPOSSIBLE
TO EXPLAIN THIS
AS ANYTHING OTHER
THAN A GENUINE UFO.
POSSIBLY ALIEN...
DEFINITELY DESTRUCTIVE.
WHAT ABOUT OUR
PROBLEM, MR. SPOCK?
ANY IDEAS ON HOW
TO GET US BACK
TO OUR OWN TIME?
A THEORY...
A REVERSE APPLICATION
OF WHAT HAPPENED TO US.
LOGICALLY, IT COULD WORK.
ALSO, LOGICALLY, THERE ARE
A HUNDRED VARIABLES,
ANY ONE OF WHICH COULD PUT
US IN A WORSE POSITION
THAN WE'RE IN NOW.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO GO BACK
AND GET THOSE REPORTS
AND PHOTOS.
IF THE CAPTAIN FEELS
DUTY BOUND TO REPORT
WHAT HE SAW,
THERE WON'T BE ANY
EVIDENCE TO BACK HIM UP.
THAT MAKES ME OUT TO BE
EITHER A LIAR OR A FOOL.
PERHAPS.
NOT AT ALL.
YOU'LL SIMPLY BE ONE
OF THE THOUSANDS
WHO THOUGHT HE SAW A UFO.
CAPTAIN, I KNOW
THAT BASE.
I WAS STATIONED
THERE A YEAR AGO.
I'D LIKE TO--
NO, CAPTAIN. THANK YOU.
BUT IF ANYTHING
SHOULD GO WRONG,
YOU MIGHT GET HURT.
WE COULDN'T RISK THAT.
NEITHER COULD YOU
OR YOUR SON.
WELL, I'D LIKE
TO HELP.
I COULD SKETCH
A LAYOUT OF
THE PLACE FOR YOU,
SHOW YOU WHERE
THE RECORD SECTION
AND THE PHOTO LAB ARE.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
PRIMITIVE COMPUTER.
I'VE SEEN THEM
DEMONSTRATED
IN MUSEUMS.
ME, TOO.
IF THIS ONE'S LIKE THOSE,
IT'LL MAKE THE DEVIL'S
OWN NOISE IF YOU START IT.
I DON'T INTEND
TO START IT.
HOW LONG HAVE THEY
BEEN DOWN THERE NOW?
15 MINUTES, 28 SECONDS.
WELL, SHOULDN'T
THEY BE COMING UP?
IT IS A FACT, DOCTOR,
THAT PROWLING BY STEALTH
IS MORE TIME-CONSUMING
THAN A DIRECT APPROACH.
IN OUR CASE A--
SHOULDN'T YOU
BE WORKING ON
YOUR TIME WARP
CALCULATIONS,
MR. SPOCK?
I AM.
HOLD IT.
GET YOUR HANDS UP.
NOW...ONE
AT A TIME--
HAND ME THOSE BELTS.
AND THE BAG.
IT'S BEEN TOO LONG.
JIM SHOULD HAVE
AT LEAST SIGNALED
BY NOW.
YOU MAY BE CORRECT,
DOCTOR.
OPEN COMMUNICATOR
CHANNEL.
[BEEP BEEP]
WHAT WAS THAT?
WHAT WAS WHAT?
THAT NOISE.
I DIDN'T HEAR
ANYTHING.
THAT NOISE.
IT'S COMING FROM
ONE OF THESE THINGS.
[BEEP BEEP]
[WHIRRING]
THE EMERGENCY
SIGNAL.
STAY RIGHT WHERE
YOU ARE.
ONE EMERGENCY SIGNAL, SIR.
BEAM UP IMMEDIATELY.
ONLY ONE SIGNAL.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE'LL KNOW
IN A MOMENT, DOCTOR.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN?
YES, I'M ALL RIGHT,
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE,
WE HAVE...ANOTHER PROBLEM.
Spock: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3113.9.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
RECORDING.
DUE TO AN UNFORTUNATE
ACCIDENT,
WE HAVE TAKEN ABOARD
ANOTHER UNWANTED PASSENGER.
YOUR SURPRISE PACKAGE
IS AN AIR POLICE SERGEANT
FROM THE BASE.
I WANT
YOU TO KEEP HIM
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
NO USE IN LETTING HIM
SEE MORE OF THE SHIP
THAN IS NECESSARY.
I DON'T BELIEVE
THERE'LL BE TROUBLE
IN THAT RESPECT, CAPTAIN.
OUR GUEST SEEMS
QUITE SATISFIED
TO REMAIN
WHERE HE IS.
KIRK OUT.
WHAT WAS
THE CHRONOMETER READING
WHEN WE FIRST SIGHTED
CHRISTOPHER'S JET?
5:30 IN THAT
TIME ZONE--
MAYBE A LITTLE
AFTER.
PUT IT AT THE END
OF THESE TAPES,
WILL YOU?
YOU'VE GOT THEM ALL NOW.
WE'LL TRY THE DARKROOM.
PHOTO LAB.
LET'S SEE. THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL OF THEM.
SIGNAL MR. SPOCK
THAT WE'RE ALMOST
READY TO BEAM UP.
I'LL MAKE A CHECK
OF THE FILES
JUST IN CASE.
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE'S THE OTHER ONE?
WHAT OTHER ONE?
YOUR PARTNER. I SAW
YOU LOOKING THAT WAY,
AND I SAW SOMEBODY
MOVE IN THERE.
NO, NO, NO. JUST ME.
BESIDES, COULD ANYONE
GET OUT OF HERE WITHOUT
YOUR SEEING THEM?
NO. NOBODY SHOULD HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO.
YOUR DECISION TO BEAM UP
WAS QUITE CORRECT, MR. SULU.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Scott: ENGINE ROOM
TO MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
WE'VE COMPLETED REENERGIZING
THE WARP ENGINES, SIR.
WE CAN REFIRE THEM ANYTIME.
DO SO NOW, ENGINEER.
WE'LL NEED ALL POWER
TO TEST OUR THEORY.
AYE, SIR. ENGINE ROOM OUT.
POOR PHOTOGRAPHY.
BLAST YOUR THEORIES
AND OBSERVATIONS,
MR. SPOCK.
WHAT ABOUT JIM?
HE'S DOWN THERE ALONE,
PROBABLY UNDER ARREST.
HE DOESN'T HAVE
A COMMUNICATOR,
AND WE CAN'T LOCATE HIM
OR BEAM HIM BACK ABOARD
WITHOUT ONE.
I AM AWARE OF THAT,
DOCTOR.
THIS IS THE FIRST OFFICER.
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
NOW, LOOK, MISTER,
YOU AND I HAD BETTER
START COMMUNICATING.
I WANT TO KNOW HOW
YOU GOT IN HERE.
NOW, THAT'S A SIMPLE
QUESTION.
GIVE ME A SIMPLE ANSWER.
NOBODY SAW YOU.
YOU GOT ALL THE WAY
INSIDE HERE WITHOUT
TRIPPING ANY ALARM.
HOW DID YOU DO IT?
BELIEVE ME, COLONEL.
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME.
DON'T TRY TO BE FUNNY.
HOW DID YOU GET IN?
I POPPED IN OUT
OF THIN AIR.
YOU SEEM TO THINK
THIS IS SOME KIND
OF A GAME.
NO, COLONEL.
I KNOW IT'S NO GAME.
ALL RIGHT. WHAT DID
YOU SAY YOUR NAME WAS?
FOR THE FOURTH TIME,
MY NAME IS
JAMES T. KIRK.
AND HOW DID YOU
GET INSIDE
A TOP SECURITY
INSTALLATION,
JAMES T. KIRK?
I TOLD YOU.
YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE ME.
UH...COLONEL,
WOULD YOU MIND
BEING CAREFUL WITH THAT?
THAT WORRIES
YOU A LITTLE, HUH?
WHAT IS THAT,
A RADIO, TRANSMITTER
OF SOME KIND?
OF SOME KIND.
YOU CAN BE
MORE SPECIFIC
THAN THAT, KIRK.
I DON'T LIKE
MYSTERIES.
IF YOU DON'T STOP
BEING CARELESS WITH THAT,
THEN YOU'LL HAVE ONE--
A BIG ONE.
I'LL HAVE IT
DISASSEMBLED
AND EXAMINED.
WE ARE NOT DUMMIES,
MISTER.
WE KNOW HOW TO
FIND OUT THINGS
WE WANT TO KNOW.
WHAT IS THAT?
IS THAT A UNIFORM
OF SOME KIND?
THIS LITTLE THING?
JUST SOMETHING
I SLIPPED ON.
KIRK, MAYBE YOU
DON'T REALIZE
HOW SERIOUS THIS IS.
SABOTAGE
OF A GOVERNMENT
INSTALLATION--
DID I SABOTAGE
SOMETHING?
NO. WE STOPPED YOU
IN TIME.
BUT WHAT WOULD YOU
HAVE DONE IF WE
HADN'T FOUND YOU?
BELIEVE ME, COLONEL,
NOTHING AT ALL.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU'RE HERE FOR,
NOTHING AT ALL?
THAT'S WHAT WOULD
HAVE HAPPENED
IF YOU HADN'T
INTERFERED.
ALL RIGHT, KIRK.
MAYBE THIS WILL
MAKE YOU LAUGH--
SABOTAGE, ESPIONAGE,
UNAUTHORIZED ENTRY,
BURGLARY!
HOW ARE THOSE
FOR STARTERS?
AND I CAN THINK UP
LOTS MORE
IF YOU DON'T
START TALKING.
ALL RIGHT, COLONEL.
THE TRUTH IS,
I'M A LITTLE GREEN MAN
FROM ALPHA CENTAURI,
A BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
YOU OUGHT TO SEE IT.
I AM GOING
TO LOCK YOU UP
FOR 200 YEARS.
THAT OUGHT TO BE
JUST ABOUT RIGHT.
HE'S PROBABLY
BEING HELD
IN SECURITY SECTION.
EVEN IF
THEY'VE NOTIFIED
THE AUTHORITIES,
IT'LL TAKE A LITTLE
TIME FOR SOMEONE
TO GET THERE.
QUITE LOGICAL, CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU GIVE US
THE COORDINATES
TO BEAM DOWN
A LANDING PARTY NEAR
THOSE INTERROGATION ROOMS?
YES. BUT YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO GET THEM
UNLESS YOU TAKE ME
WITH YOU.
I CAN'T DO THAT,
CAPTAIN.
IF SOMETHING
WENT WRONG--
SOMETHING'S
ALREADY GONE WRONG.
OF COURSE,
YOU COULD BEAM DOWN
ANYWHERE INSIDE
THAT BASE,
BUT IT WOULD TAKE
TIME TO FIND HIM.
MR. SULU,
YOU AND CAPTAIN
CHRISTOPHER
WILL BEAM DOWN
WITH ME.
THE CAPTAIN WILL PROVIDE
THE COORDINATES
FOR THE TRANSPORTER CHIEF.
SHALL I ISSUE
PHASERS?
ONE FOR YOU, ONE FOR ME.
SET THEM ON
HEAVY STUN FORCE.
YES, SIR.
YOU DON'T TRUST ME,
SPOCK.
IN FACT, I DO...
BUT ONLY
TO A CERTAIN POINT.
ENERGIZE.
DO THEY DO THAT
ALL THE TIME?
ARE YOU HUNGRY?
UH-HUH.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE?
MAYBE SOME
CHICKEN SOUP.
IT IS.
JUST A MINUTE, SIR.
HOLD IT.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
SEE WHAT THAT IS,
AIRMAN.
DON'T YOU FIND THAT
PAINFUL, CAPTAIN?
YES, I DO.
WHAT'S HE
DOING HERE?
HE KNEW THE EXACT
BEAM DOWN COORDINATES FOR
THIS SECTION OF THE BASE.
IT WAS NECESSARY
TO BRING HIM ALONG.
I SEE. WELL,
NO HARM DONE.
Kirk: MR. SULU, DID YOU
HAVE A CHANCE TO
CHECK OUT THOSE TAPES?
MR. SPOCK
RAN THEM THROUGH
OUR COMPUTERS.
THEY WERE
THE RIGHT ONES.
GOOD.
WE GOT THEM ALL.
THEY KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN HERE.
ALL THEY HAVE IS A MYSTERY
AND NO ANSWERS.
MR. SULU, SIGNAL
THE TRANSPORTER CHIEF.
FOUR TO BEAM UP.
UH-UH. NOT ME.
DON'T BE A FOOL.
YOU KNOW
WHAT'S AT STAKE.
YOU BET I DO--
MY FAMILY.
A SON THAT ISN'T
BORN YET.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
RETURN ME NOW,
CAPTAIN.
SPOCK,
COME OUT OF THERE.
YOU CAN'T EXPLAIN
YOUR PRESENCE ON
THE BASE.
I TOLD YOU,
IT'S MY DUTY TO REPORT
EVERYTHING I'VE SEEN.
THAT'S EXPLANATION
ENOUGH.
SPOCK!
YOU'LL GO HOME,
CHRISTOPHER...
BUT YOU'LL DO IT
OUR WAY.
OVER MY DEAD BODY.
I SUSPECTED
HE MIGHT NOT WISH
TO RETURN WITH US.
FOUR TO BEAM UP,
MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3114.1.
WE MUST MAKE AN ATTEMPT
TO BREAK FREE OF THIS TIME,
OR WE AND OUR
RELUCTANT PASSENGERS
WILL REMAIN ITS PRISONERS.
ALL WE HAVE IS A THEORY
AND A FEW FACTS.
MR. SCOTT AND I
BOTH AGREE
THAT THE ONLY
POSSIBLE SOLUTION
IS THE SLINGSHOT
EFFECT,
LIKE THE ONE
THAT PUT US HERE.
MY COMPUTATIONS INDICATE
THAT IF WE FLY
TOWARD THE SUN,
SEEK OUT ITS
MAGNETIC ATTRACTION,
THEN PULL AWAY
AT FULL POWER,
THE WHIPLASH
WILL PROPEL US INTO
ANOTHER TIME WARP.
SLINGSHOT EFFECTS
ARE FINE FOR YOU PEOPLE.
HOW DO YOU
PROPOSE TO RETURN
THE SERGEANT AND ME?
LOGICALLY,
AS WE MOVE FASTER
AND FASTER TOWARD THE SUN,
WE'LL BEGIN TO MOVE
BACKWARD IN TIME.
WE'LL ACTUALLY GO BACK
BEYOND YESTERDAY,
BEYOND THE POINT
WHEN WE FIRST APPEARED
IN THE SKY.
THEN, BREAKING FREE
WILL SHOOT US
FORWARD IN TIME,
AND WE'LL TRANSPORT YOU
BACK AT A POINT BEFORE
ANY OF THIS HAPPENED.
YOU WON'T HAVE
ANYTHING TO REMEMBER
BECAUSE IT NEVER
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED.
WHAT IF YOU
CAN'T PULL FREE
OF THE SUN?
OH, WE'LL DO THAT
ALL RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
WE'LL NOT BE
GETTING SO CLOSE
THAT MY ENGINES
COULDN'T PULL US OUT.
WHAT I AM WORRIED
ABOUT, SIR--
THAT WE MAY NOT
HAVE MUCH CONTROL
WHEN WE'RE THROWN
FORWARD AGAIN.
HELM CONTROL?
BRAKING CONTROL, SIR.
IF I CAN'T STOP US
SOON ENOUGH,
WE MAY OVERSHOOT
OUR TIME,
AND IF I STOP
THE ENGINES SUDDENLY,
THE STRAIN MAY
TEAR US APART.
ANY WAY WE DO IT,
IT MEANS A MIGHTY ROUGH RIDE.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
WE ALL HAVE TO TAKE A CHANCE--
ESPECIALLY
IF ONE IS ALL YOU HAVE.
ASSUME YOUR
STATIONS.
Man on radio:
AFFIRMATIVE.
Second man on radio:
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
ENVIRONMENTAL CONTROL
NEGATIVE...
ENGINEERING CONTROL,
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 3,
MR. SULU.
WARP FACTOR 3, SIR.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D
MAKE IT INTO SPACE.
I WAS IN LINE
TO BE CHOSEN FOR
THE SPACE PROGRAM,
BUT I DIDN'T QUALIFY.
TAKE A GOOD LOOK
AROUND, CAPTAIN.
YOU MADE IT HERE
AHEAD OF ALL OF THEM.
SIR, OUR SPEED
IS INCREASING.
WE'RE TRAVELING
AT MORE THAN
WARP 8.
MR. SPOCK.
SINCE WE'VE PASSED
MERCURY,
THE SUN'S PULL ON US
HAS INCREASED GREATLY.
FROM HERE,
WE'LL MOVE EVEN FASTER.
AND, CAPTAIN,
NOTICE THE CHRONOMETERS.
THEY'VE STARTED
BACKWARD.
MINUTE BY MINUTE,
THE SPEED
OF TIME PASSAGE
WILL NOW INCREASE.
GET YOUR GEAR.
REPORT TO THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AND, CAPTAIN
CHRISTOPHER,
YOU ONLY HAVE
ABOUT 15 YEARS,
SO YOU'D BETTER HURRY.
APPROACHING
BREAKAWAY POINT.
ON THE COUNTDOWN.
10...
9...8...
7...6...
5...4...
3...2...
NOW, MR. SULU.
MORE POWER, MR. SULU.
IT'S MAXIMUM NOW,
SIR. AND SHE'S
FIGHTING IT.
Man on radio: ...POINT 5
HERE. CAN WE CONFIRM?
GRAVITY IS DOWN
TO POINT 8.
WE'VE BROKEN FREE
AND HEADING BACK.
GAINING SPEED NOW,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE NOW AT WARP 4.
WARP 7.
8.
OFF THE DIAL, SIR.
CHRONOMETER
IS MOVING FORWARD
AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE
THE CHRONOMETER READING
AND THE COORDINATES TO
RETURN CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER
AND THE GUARD?
COMPUTED.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
CAPTAIN CHRISTOPHER.
THIS IS CHRISTOPHER.
WE'RE COMING UP
ON EARTH FAST, CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU READY?
EVERYTHING A-OK.
UH, CAPTAIN...
THANKS FOR
THE LOOK AHEAD.
OUR PLEASURE,
CAPTAIN.
BRIDGE OUT.
20 MINUTES, SIR.
IT'LL BE CLOSE.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
PREPARE TO ENERGIZE.
10 MINUTES.
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...4...
3...2...
ENERGIZE.
Blackjack:
YOU SHOULD BE
CLOSE ENOUGH
FOR A VISUAL CONTACT.
BLUEJAY 4.
CAN YOU SEE IT?
WHAT IS IT?
BLUEJAY 4. COME IN.
WE'VE LOST THE IMAGE.
BLACKJACK,
THIS IS BLUEJAY 4.
I COULD HAVE SWORN
THERE WAS SOME KIND
OF SHIP, BUT...
NOTHING COULD HAVE
MOVED THAT FAST.
WE DON'T TRACK MIRAGES.
MARK IT DOWN
AS ANOTHER UFO.
BLUEJAY 4
RETURNING TO BASE.
OUT.
APPROACHING
SECOND BEAMING, CAPTAIN.
BRIDGE
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM,
PREPARE TO ENERGIZE.
NOW.
ENERGIZE.
PAST PLUTO, SIR.
WHAT'S OUR READING,
MR. SPOCK?
APPROACHING
OUR CENTURY, CAPTAIN.
BRAKING SHOULD BEGIN...
NOW.
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
BEGIN FULL BRAKING POWER.
PULLING AWAY FROM THE SUN
WEAKENED THEM, SIR.
THEY MAY BLOW APART
IF I REVERSE.
NO CHOICE, MR. SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
50 YEARS TO GO.
ENGINES CUTTING
BACK, SIR.
NO DECREASE
IN SPEED.
40...
30...
NEVER MIND,
MR. SPOCK.
THE ENGINES!
ENGINE ROOM TO BRIDGE.
ENGINES ARE ON
FULL REVERSE,
AND THEY'RE BUCKLING!
BRIDGE!
MR. SCOTT
IS STILL WITH US.
CAPTAIN.
STARFLEET CONTROL
CALLING "ENTERPRISE."
COME IN, "ENTERPRISE."
OPEN A CHANNEL, UHURA.
FREQUENCY OPEN, SIR.
STARFLEET CONTROL,
THIS IS THE "ENTERPRISE."
CAPTAIN KIRK SPEAKING.
Computer:
RECORD SHIP ARRIVAL, DEAR.
"ENTERPRISE," THIS IS
STARFLEET CONTROL.
COME IN, PLEASE.
STARFLEET CONTROL,
REPEATING MESSAGE.
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS HOME.
KIRK OUT.