CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2947.3.
WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH
A SEVERE ION STORM.
ONE CREWMAN IS DEAD.
THE SHIP'S DAMAGE
IS CONSIDERABLE.
I HAVE ORDERED
A NONSCHEDULED LAYOVER
ON STARBASE 11
FOR REPAIRS.
A FULL REPORT OF DAMAGES
WAS MADE
TO THE COMMANDING OFFICER
OF STARBASE 11--
COMMODORE STONE.
MAINTENANCE,
SECTION 18.
THE SECTION IS WORKING
ON THE INTREPID.
RESCHEDULE. THE ENTERPRISE
IS ON PRIORITY 1.
THAT MAKES THREE TIMES
YOU'VE READ IT, JIM.
IS THERE AN ERROR?
NO.
BUT THE DEATH
OF THE CREWMAN...
REGULATIONS, CAPTAIN.
AND THE EXTRACT FROM
YOUR SHIP'S COMPUTER LOG
CONFIRMING THIS
SWORN DEPOSITION?
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
[UHURA]
BRIDGE HERE.
GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
WHERE'S MR. SPOCK WITH
THAT COMPUTER LOG EXTRACT?
HE SHOULD
HAVE BEEN THERE
10 MINUTES AGO, SIR.
KIRK OUT.
IT'S A GREAT PITY.
THE SERVICE CAN'T
AFFORD
TO LOSE MEN
LIKE LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY.
I AGREE.
I WAITED UNTIL
THE LAST POSSIBLE MOMENT.
WE WERE ON RED ALERT,
THE STORM GOT WORSE.
I HAD TO JETTISON
THE POD.
WHAT TOOK YOU SO LONG,
MR. SPOCK?
CAPTAIN...
I BELIEVE--
I'LL TAKE THAT.
JAME.
THERE YOU ARE.
I JUST WANTED ONE MORE
LOOK AT YOU--THE MAN
WHO KILLED MY FATHER.
THAT'S NOT SO.
HE WAS MY FRIEND.
YOUR FRIEND?
YOU HATED HIM
ALL YOUR LIFE!
THAT'S WHY
YOU KILLED HIM,
YOU MURDERER!
JAME.
MR. SPOCK,
WOULD YOU PLEASE...
MISS FINNEY,
COME WITH ME,
PLEASE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
YOU SAY YOU JETTISONED
THE POD AFTER THE RED ALERT?
YOU HAVE
MY SWORN DEPOSITION.
THEN, CAPTAIN,
I MUST PRESUME
YOU HAVE COMMITTED
WILLFUL PERJURY.
THIS EXTRACT FROM
YOUR COMPUTER LOG SAYS
YOU JETTISONED THE POD
BEFORE GOING
TO RED ALERT.
CONSIDER YOURSELF
CONFINED TO THE BASE.
AN OFFICIAL INQUIRY
WILL DETERMINE
WHETHER A GENERAL
COURT-MARTIAL IS IN ORDER.
SPACE-- THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2948.5.
STARSHIP ENTERPRISE
REMAINS IN ORBIT
AROUND STARBASE 11.
FULL REPAIR
IS IN PROGRESS.
I HAVE BEEN ORDERED
TO STAND BY ON STARBASE 11
UNTIL THE INQUIRY
INTO THE DEATH OF
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER FINNEY
CAN BE CONDUCTED.
I'M CONFIDENT
OF THE OUTCOME.
TIMOTHY,
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
SINCE THE VULCANIAN
EXPEDITION.
WELL, I SEE
OUR GRADUATING CLASS
FROM THE ACADEMY
IS WELL REPRESENTED.
ARGAN, HELLER...
HOW YOU DOING, MIKE?
I'LL GET BY, JIM.
I UNDERSTAND
YOU'RE LAYING OVER
FOR REPAIRS.
BIG JOB?
COUPLE OF DAYS.
YOU MOVING OUT THEN?
IN A HURRY TO SEE ME GO?
OH, I JUST WONDERED
HOW LONG IT WOULD
TAKE YOU
TO GET A NEW
RECORDS OFFICER.
YOU CAN TALK
PLAINER THAN THAT.
I CAN,
BUT I THINK
THE POINT'S
BEEN MADE.
BEN WAS A FRIEND
OF OURS.
COME ON, JIM,
LET'S GO.
NO, GO ON. FINISH.
BEN WAS A FRIEND
OF YOURS, AND...
JIM.
GO ON.
I'M WAITING
TO HEAR THE REST.
WHY DON'T
YOU TELL US?
WHAT WOULD BE THE POINT?
YOU'VE ALREADY
MADE UP YOUR MINDS.
EXCUSE ME, BONES.
IF YOU HAVE ANY DOUBT,
THAT WAS INDEED
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
YES, I KNOW.
ARE YOU
A FRIEND OF HIS?
IN THESE TRYING TIMES,
ONE OF THE FEW.
DR. LEONARD McCOY.
AND YOU?
AREEL SHAW.
AND I'M A FRIEND,
TOO...
AN OLD ONE.
ALL OF MY OLD FRIENDS
LOOK LIKE DOCTORS.
ALL OF HIS LOOK
LIKE YOU.
WELL, YOU MIGHT AS WELL
JOIN ME FOR A DRINK.
WITH THIS INQUIRY
COMING UP,
HE'S GOING TO NEED
ALL THE FRIENDS
HE CAN GET.
[CLICK]
RECORDING INQUIRY.
MATTER-- CAPTAIN KIRK,
JAMES T.
SUBJECT--
CIRCUMSTANCES OF DEATH,
LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY,
BENJAMIN.
THIS INQUIRY TO DETERMINE
WHETHER A GENERAL
COURT-MARTIAL
SHOULD BE CONVENED
AGAINST CAPTAIN KIRK.
THE CHARGES OF PERJURY
AND CULPABLE NEGLIGENCE.
READY.
LET US BEGIN
WITH YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH COMMANDER FINNEY.
YOU KNEW HIM FOR
A LONG TIME, DIDN'T YOU?
YES. HE WAS
AN INSTRUCTOR
AT THE ACADEMY
WHEN I WAS
A MIDSHIPMAN.
THAT DIDN'T STAND
IN THE WAY
OF OUR BEGINNING
A CLOSE FRIENDSHIP.
HIS DAUGHTER JAME,
WHO WAS HERE LAST
NIGHT,
WAS NAMED AFTER ME.
IT'S COMMON KNOWLEDGE
THAT SOMETHING HAPPENED
TO YOUR FRIENDSHIP.
IT'S NO SECRET.
WE WERE ASSIGNED
TO THE SAME SHIP
SOME YEARS LATER.
I RELIEVED HIM
ON WATCH ONCE
AND FOUND A CIRCUIT
OPEN TO THE ATOMIC
MATTER PILES
THAT SHOULD'VE
BEEN CLOSED.
ANOTHER
FIVE MINUTES,
IT COULD HAVE
BLOWN UP THE SHIP.
SHIP NOMENCLATURE--
SPECIFY.
UNITED STARSHIP
REPUBLIC,
NUMBER 1371.
CONTINUE.
I CLOSED THE SWITCH
AND LOGGED
THE INCIDENT.
HE DREW A REPRIMAND
AND WAS SENT TO
THE BOTTOM OF
THE PROMOTION LIST.
AND HE BLAMED YOU
FOR THAT?
YES.
HE HAD BEEN
AT THE ACADEMY
FOR AN UNUSUALLY
LONG TIME AS
AN INSTRUCTOR.
AS A RESULT,
HE WAS LATE
IN BEING ASSIGNED
TO A STARSHIP.
THE DELAY, HE FELT,
LOOKED BAD ON
HIS RECORD.
MY ACTION,
HE BELIEVED,
MADE THINGS WORSE.
COMMENT--
SERVICE RECORD
OF LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY
TO BE APPENDED
THIS INQUIRY.
NOTED.
NOW, LET'S GET INTO
THE SPECIFICS OF
THE STORM, CAPTAIN.
WEATHER SCAN
INDICATED AN ION STORM
DEAD AHEAD.
I SENT FINNEY
INTO THE POD.
WHY FINNEY?
HIS NAME WAS
AT THE TOP OF
THE DUTY ROSTER.
IF HE BLAMED YOU--
HE MAY HAVE
BLAMED ME
THAT HE NEVER ROSE
TO COMMAND A SHIP,
BUT I DON'T ASSIGN
JOBS ON THE BASIS
OF WHO BLAMES ME.
IT WAS
FINNEY'S TURN,
AND I ASSIGNED HIM.
HE HAD JUST
CHECKED IN WITH ME
FROM THE POD
WHEN WE HIT
THE LEADING EDGE
OF THE STORM.
NOT TOO BAD
AT FIRST...
I SIGNALED
A YELLOW ALERT.
THEN WE BEGAN
ENCOUNTERING
PRESSURE,
VARIANT STRESS,
FORCE 7, THE WORKS.
I FINALLY SIGNALED
A RED ALERT.
FINNEY KNEW HE HAD
A MATTER OF SECONDS.
I GAVE HIM
THOSE SECONDS
AND MORE.
BUT...
APPARENTLY
IT WASN'T ENOUGH.
THEN WHY CAPTAIN, DOES THE
COMPUTER LOG FROM YOUR SHIP
MADE AUTOMATICALLY
AT THE TIME,
INDICATE THAT YOU WERE
STILL ON YELLOW ALERT
WHEN YOU JETTISONED
AND NOT ON RED?
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE'S BEEN
A MISTAKE.
IT WOULD SEEM SO.
COULD THE COMPUTER
BE WRONG?
MR. SPOCK IS
RUNNING A SURVEY
RIGHT NOW,
BUT THE ODDS ARE
NEXT TO IMPOSSIBLE.
STOP RECORDING.
NOW, LOOK, JIM...
NOT ONE MAN
IN A MILLION
COULD DO WHAT YOU
AND I HAVE DONE--
COMMAND A STARSHIP.
A HUNDRED
DECISIONS A DAY,
HUNDREDS OF LIVES
STAKED ON YOU MAKING
EVERY ONE OF THEM RIGHT.
YOU'RE PLAYED OUT, JIM.
EXHAUSTED.
IS THAT THE WAY
YOU SEE IT?
THAT'S THE WAY
MY REPORT WILL READ
IF YOU COOPERATE.
PHYSICAL BREAKDOWN,
POSSIBLY EVEN MENTAL
COLLAPSE?
POSSIBLY.
I'D BE ADMITTING
THAT A MAN DIED
BECAUSE--
ADMIT NOTHING.
SAY NOTHING.
LET ME BURY
THE MATTER HERE AND NOW.
NO STARSHIP CAPTAIN
HAS EVER STOOD TRIAL BEFORE,
AND I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE THE FIRST.
BUT IF WHAT YOU SUSPECT
IS TRUE, THEN I'M
GUILTY.
I SHOULD BE PUNISHED.
I'M THINKING
OF THE SERVICE.
I WON'T
HAVE IT SMEARED.
BY WHAT,
COMMODORE STONE?
ALL RIGHT...
BY AN EVIDENT PERJURER
WHO IS EITHER COVERING UP
HIS BAD JUDGMENT,
HIS COWARDICE, OR
SOMETHING EVEN WORSE--
THAT'S AS FAR
AS YOU GO, SIR.
I'M TELLING YOU
I WAS THERE
ON THE BRIDGE.
I KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW WHAT I DID.
IT'S IN THE TRANSCRIPT,
AND COMPUTER TRANSCRIPTS
DON'T LIE.
NOW, I'M TELLING YOU,
CAPTAIN,
EITHER YOU ACCEPT
A PERMANENT
GROUND ASSIGNMENT,
OR THE WHOLE
DISCIPLINARY WEIGHT
OF STARFLEET COMMAND
IS GOING TO ALIGHT
RIGHT ON YOUR NECK.
SO THAT'S THE WAY
WE DO IT NOW--
SWEEP IT
UNDER THE RUG
AND ME ALONG
WITH IT?
NOT ON YOUR LIFE.
I INTEND TO FIGHT.
THEN YOU DRAW
A GENERAL COURT.
DRAW IT?
I DEMAND IT.
AND RIGHT NOW,
COMMODORE STONE.
RIGHT NOW.
CAPTAIN'S LOG
STARDATE 2948.9
THE OFFICERS WHO WILL COMPRISE
MY COURT-MARTIAL BOARD
ARE PROCEEDING
TO STARBASE 11.
MEANWHILE, REPAIRS
ON THE ENTERPRISE
ARE ALMOST COMPLETE.
AREEL...
DR. McCOY SAID
YOU WERE HERE.
I SHOULD HAVE
FELT IT IN THE AIR
LIKE STATIC ELECTRICITY.
FLATTERY WILL
GET YOU EVERYWHERE.
IT'S BEEN...
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
FOUR YEARS, SEVEN
MONTHS, AND AN ODD
NUMBER OF DAYS--
NOT THAT
I'M COUNTING.
YOU LOOK MARVELOUS.
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED
A BIT.
BUT THINGS HAVE
CHANGED FOR YOU,
HAVEN'T THEY?
OH, YOU'VE HEARD
ABOUT THAT?
I'M A LAWYER IN
THE JUDGE ADVOCATE'S
OFFICE, REMEMBER?
I REMEMBER.
LET'S FORGET IT.
WE HAVE A LOT
OF LOST TIME
TO MAKE UP FOR.
YOU'RE TAKING IT
VERY LIGHTLY.
THE CONFIDENCE OF
AN INNOCENT MAN.
ARE YOU?
MM-HMM.
THAT'S NOT WHAT
THE RUMORS INDICATE.
LOOK--
LET'S NOT TALK SHOP.
JIM, THIS
COULD RUIN YOU.
WILL YOU TAKE
SOME ADVICE?
I NEVER COULD
TALK YOU INTO ANYTHING.
ALL RIGHT. FIRE AWAY.
THE PROSECUTION WILL
BUILD ITS CASE,
ON THE BASIS OF KIRK
VERSUS THE COMPUTER.
NOW, IF YOUR
ATTORNEY TRIES TO
DEFEND
ON THAT BASIS,
YOU WON'T HAVE
A CHANCE.
WHAT OTHER CHOICE
IS THERE?
THAT'S UP TO
YOUR ATTORNEY,
AND THAT'S WHY
HE'S GOT TO BE
A GOOD ONE.
YOU, PERHAPS?
NO. I--
I'M BUSY.
WELL...
A GIRL WITH YOUR
ABILITY
SHOULD BE ABLE TO
HANDLE TWO CASES AT ONCE.
JIM, BE SERIOUS.
YOU'RE NOT
AN ORDINARY HUMAN.
YOU'RE A STARSHIP
CAPTAIN,
AND YOU'VE STEPPED
INTO SCANDAL.
IF THERE'S ANY WAY
THEY CAN DO IT,
THEY'LL
SLAP YOU DOWN HARD
AND PERMANENTLY
FOR THE GOOD
OF THE SERVICE.
YOU STILL HAVEN'T MADE
ANY RECOMMENDATION.
SAMUEL T. COGLEY,
ATTORNEY-AT-LAW.
IF ANYONE CAN
SAVE YOU, HE CAN.
HE'LL BE PAYING YOU
A VISIT.
JIM, I'VE GOT TO GO.
AREEL...
YOU STILL HAVEN'T TOLD ME
HOW YOU KNOW SO MUCH
ABOUT WHAT
THE PROSECUTION'S
GOING TO DO.
BECAUSE, JIM KIRK,
MY DEAR OLD LOVE...
I AM THE PROSECUTION,
AND I HAVE TO DO
MY VERY BEST TO HAVE
YOU SLAPPED DOWN HARD,
BROKEN
OUT OF THE SERVICE...
IN DISGRACE.
YOU KIRK?
YES.
WHAT IS ALL THIS?
I FIGURED WE'D BE
SPENDING SOME TIME
TOGETHER,
SO I MOVED IN.
I HOPE I'M NOT
CROWDING YOU.
WHAT'S THE
MATTER?
DON'T
YOU LIKE BOOKS?
OH, I LIKE THEM FINE,
BUT A COMPUTER
TAKES LESS SPACE.
HUH. A COMPUTER.
I GOT ONE OF THESE
IN MY OFFICE.
CONTAINS
ALL THE PRECEDENTS.
A SYNTHESIS OF ALL THE
GREAT LEGAL DECISIONS
WRITTEN THROUGHOUT TIME.
I NEVER USE IT.
WHY NOT?
I'VE GOT MY OWN SYSTEM.
BOOKS, YOUNG MAN, BOOKS.
THOUSANDS OF THEM.
IF TIME WASN'T SO IMPORTANT,
I'D SHOW YOU
SOMETHING--MY LIBRARY.
THOUSANDS OF BOOKS.
WHAT WOULD BE THE
POINT?
THIS IS WHERE
THE LAW IS,
NOT IN THAT HOMOGENIZED,
PASTEURIZED, SYNTHESIZED--
DO YOU WANT TO
KNOW THE LAW--
THE ANCIENT CONCEPTS
IN THEIR OWN LANGUAGE,
LEARN THE INTENT
OF THE MEN
WHO WROTE THEM,
FROM MOSES
TO THE TRIBUNAL
OF ALPHA 3?
BOOKS.
YOU HAVE TO BE EITHER
AN EXCESSIVE CRACK BUD
WHO'S ESCAPED
FROM HIS KEEPER
OR SAMUEL T. COGLEY,
ATTORNEY-AT-LAW.
RIGHT ON BOTH COUNTS.
NEED A LAWYER?
I'M AFRAID SO.
♪
THIS COURT IS NOW
IN SESSION.
I HAVE APPOINTED
AS MEMBERS OF THIS COURT
SPACE COMMAND
REPRESENTATIVE LINDSTROM,
STARSHIP CAPTAIN KRASNOVSKY,
AND CHONDRA.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I DIRECT YOUR ATTENTION
TO THE FACT
THAT YOU HAVE
A RIGHT TO ASK FOR
SUBSTITUTE OFFICERS
IF YOU FEEL THAT
ANY OF THESE NAMED
HARBOR PREJUDICED
ATTITUDES
TO YOUR CASE.
I HAVE NO
OBJECTIONS, SIR.
DO YOU CONSENT
TO THE SERVICE OF
LIEUTENANT SHAW
AS PROSECUTING OFFICER
AND TO MYSELF
AS PRESIDENT OF THE COURT?
I DO, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, CLERK.
CHARGE-- CULPABLE
NEGLIGENCE.
SPECIFICATION-- IN THAT
ON STARDATE 2945.7,
BY SUCH NEGLIGENCE,
CAPTAIN KIRK, JAMES T.,
DID CAUSE LOSS OF LIFE,
TO WIT, THE LIFE
OF RECORDS OFFICER
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
FINNEY, BENJAMIN.
TO ALL RECORDED CHARGES
AND SPECIFICATIONS,
WHAT IS THE PLEA?
NOT GUILTY.
PROCEED, LIEUTENANT.
I CALL MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK, SERIAL NUMBER
S-179-276-SP.
SERVICE RANK--
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER.
POSITION-- FIRST OFFICER,
SCIENCE OFFICER.
CURRENT ASSIGNMENT--
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
COMMENDATIONS-- VULCANIAN
SCIENTIFIC LEGION OF HONOR.
AWARDS OF VALOR--
TWICE DECORATED
BY STARFLEET COMMAND.
MR. SPOCK,
AS A FIRST OFFICER,
YOU KNOW
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT
COMPUTERS, DON'T YOU?
I KNOW
ALL ABOUT THEM.
IT IS POSSIBLE FOR
A COMPUTER TO MALFUNCTION,
IS IT NOT?
AFFIRMATIVE.
DO YOU KNOW
OF ANY MALFUNCTION
WHICH HAS CAUSED
AN INACCURACY IN
THE ENTERPRISE COMPUTER?
NEGATIVE.
THAT ANSWER IS BASED ON
YOUR MECHANICAL SURVEY
OF THE ENTERPRISE
COMPUTER
ORDERED BY THE DEFENDANT
PRIOR TO THIS TRIAL,
IS IT NOT?
AFFIRMATIVE.
NOW THE STARDATE--
BUT THE COMPUTER
IS INACCURATE,
NEVERTHELESS.
WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
IT REPORTS THAT
THE JETTISON BUTTON
WAS PRESSED BEFORE
THE RED ALERT.
IN OTHER WORDS, IT REPORTS
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
WAS REACTING TO
AN EXTREME EMERGENCY
THAT DID NOT
THEN EXIST.
AND THAT
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
IS IT?
WERE YOU WATCHING HIM
THE EXACT MOMENT
HE PRESSED
THE JETTISON BUTTON?
NO. I WAS OCCUPIED.
THE SHIP WAS ALREADY
ON YELLOW ALERT.
THEN HOW CAN YOU
DISPUTE THE FINDING
OF THE LOG?
I DO NOT DISPUTE IT.
I MERELY STATE
THAT IT IS WRONG.
OH? ON WHAT DO YOU
BASE THAT STATEMENT?
I KNOW THE CAPTAIN.
HE IS IN--
PLEASE INSTRUCT
THE WITNESS
NOT TO SPECULATE.
LIEUTENANT,
I AM HALF VULCANIAN.
VULCANIANS
DO NOT SPECULATE.
I SPEAK
FROM PURE LOGIC.
IF I LET GO OF
A HAMMER
ON A PLANET
THAT HAS A POSITIVE
GRAVITY,
I NEED NOT
SEE IT FALL
TO KNOW THAT IT HAS,
IN FACT, FALLEN.
I DO NOT SEE WHAT--
GENTLEMEN,
HUMAN BEINGS HAVE
CHARACTERISTICS
JUST AS INANIMATE
OBJECTS DO.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE
FOR CAPTAIN KIRK
TO ACT OUT OF PANIC
OR MALICE.
IT IS NOT
HIS NATURE.
IN YOUR OPINION.
YES. IN MY OPINION.
THANK YOU.
YOUR WITNESS,
MR. COGLEY.
NO QUESTIONS.
YOU MAY
STEP DOWN.
I NOW CALL
THE PERSONNEL OFFICER
FOR THE ENTERPRISE.
SERVICE RANK-- ENSIGN.
POSITION--
PERSONNEL OFFICER.
CURRENT ASSIGNMENT--
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
IN THE COURSE
OF YOUR DUTIES
AS PERSONNEL OFFICER
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
YOU WOULD BE FAMILIAR
WITH THE SERVICE RECORDS
OF ALL ABOARD?
YES, MA'AM.
WITH REFERENCE TO
RECORDS OFFICER FINNEY,
WAS THERE
IN HIS SERVICE RECORD
A REPORTED
DISCIPLINARY ACTION
FOR FAILURE
TO CLOSE A CIRCUIT?
YES, MA'AM.
WAS THE CHARGE
IN THAT INSTANCE
BASED UPON A LOG ENTRY
BY THE OFFICER
WHO RELIEVED HIM?
YES, MA'AM.
AND WHO WAS THAT OFFICER?
ENSIGN JAMES T. KIRK.
LOUDER, PLEASE,
FOR THE COURT.
ENSIGN JAMES T. KIRK.
NOW THE CAPTAIN KIRK
WHO SITS IN THIS
COURTROOM?
YES, MA'AM.
THANK YOU.
DO YOU WISH
TO CROSS-EXAMINE.
MR. COGLEY?
NO QUESTIONS.
YOU MAY STEP DOWN.
I NOW CALL
DR. McCOY
TO THE STAND.
SERVICE RANK--
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER.
POSITION-- SHIP'S SURGEON.
CURRENT ASSIGNMENT--
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
COMMENDATIONS--
LEGION OF HONOR.
AWARDS OF VALOR-- DECORATED
BY STARFLEET SURGEONS.
DOCTOR, YOU ARE
ON THE RECORD
AN EXPERT IN PSYCHOLOGY,
ESPECIALLY
SPACE PSYCHOLOGY--
PATTERNS WHICH DEVELOP
IN THE CLOSE QUARTERS
OF A SHIP
DURING LONG VOYAGES
IN DEEP SPACE.
I KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
YOU HAVE
JUST HEARD TESTIMONY
OF YOUR OWN
PERSONNEL OFFICER,
THAT IT WAS AN ACTION
OF THE THEN ENSIGN KIRK
WHICH PLACED
AN UNERASABLE BLOT
ON THE RECORD
OF THE THEN
LIEUTENANT FINNEY.
PSYCHOLOGICALLY,
DOCTOR, IS IT POSSIBLE
THAT LIEUTENANT
FINNEY BLAMED KIRK
FOR THE INCIDENT?
IT'S POSSIBLE.
HE COULD HAVE HATED KIRK
DOWN THROUGH THE YEARS,
BLAMED HIM FOR BEING
PASSED OVER FOR PROMOTION,
BLAMED HIM FOR NEVER
BEING GIVEN A COMMAND
OF HIS OWN, CORRECT?
HE COULD HAVE.
NOW LET US
HYPOTHESIZE, DOCTOR.
IS IT NORMAL FOR A PERSON
TO RETURN AFFECTION
FOR HATRED?
NO.
DO WE NOT TEND TO
AT FIRST RESENT AND THEN
ACTIVELY DISLIKE
THE PERSON
WHO HATES US?
WAIT A MINUTE.
I DON'T QUITE
FOLLOW YOU.
HYPOTHETICALLY.
WOULD NOT CAPTAIN SMITH
BEGIN TO HATE LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER JONES
ONCE HE LEARNED THAT
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER JONES
HATED AND DETESTED HIM?
WELL, YES, I SUPPOSE
IT COULD HAPPEN.
THEN I ASK YOU,
IS IT NOT POSSIBLE
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
BECAME AWARE
OF LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
FINNEY'S HATRED TOWARD HIM
AND PERHAPS,
EVEN INVOLUNTARILY,
BEGAN TO RECIPROCATE?
NOT CAPTAIN KIRK.
ANY NORMAL HUMAN, DOCTOR.
IS IT POSSIBLE?
BUT HE'S NOT THAT
KIND OF A MAN.
IS IT THEORETICALLY
POSSIBLE, DOCTOR?
YES.
IT'S POSSIBLE.
THANK YOU.
YOUR WITNESS,
MR. COGLEY.
NO QUESTIONS.
YOU MAY STEP DOWN.
MR. COGLEY...
YOU HAVE LISTENED
TO TESTIMONY
FROM THREE WITNESSES,
AND IN NEITHER INSTANCE
HAVE YOU AVAILED YOURSELF
OF YOUR RIGHT
TO CROSS-EXAMINE.
HAVE YOU ABROGATED
THAT RIGHT?
WELL, SIR,
THE TRUTH IS, I'VE
BEEN HOLDING BACK
TILL WE GET THIS
PRELIMINARY
BUSINESS
OUT OF THE WAY.
I'D LIKE TO CALL
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THE STAND.
JAMES T. KIRK, SERIAL
NUMBER SC-937-0176-CEC.
SERVICE RANK-- CAPTAIN.
POSITION-- STARSHIP COMMAND.
CURRENT ASSIGNMENT--
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
COMMENDATIONS-- PALM LEAF
OF AXINAR PEACE MISSION,
GRAND KITE
ORDER OF TACTICS,
CLASS OF EXCELLENCE,
FRENTERUS RIBBON
OF COMMENDATION,
CLASSES FIRST--
MAY IT PLEASE
THE COURT...
COURT RECOGNIZES
COUNSEL FOR
THE PROSECUTION.
THE PROSECUTION CONCEDES
THE INESTIMABLE RECORD
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
MR. COGLEY?
I WOULDN'T WANT TO SLOW
THE WHEELS OF PROGRESS,
BUT THEN, ON
THE OTHER HAND,
I WOULDN'T WANT
THOSE WHEELS TO
RUN OVER MY CLIENT
IN THEIR
UNBRIDLED HASTE.
CONTINUE.
AWARDS OF VALOR--
MEDAL OF HONOR,
SILVER PALM WITH CLUSTER,
STARFLEET CITATION
FOR CONSPICUOUS GALLANTRY,
CARRAGITE ORDER
OF HEROISM--
STOP.
I THINK
THAT'S ENOUGH.
I WOULDN'T WANT
TO SLOW THINGS UP
TOO MUCH.
THANK YOU.
NOW, CAPTAIN,
DESPITE WHAT THESE
MACHINES INDICATE,
WAS THERE INDEED
A RED ALERT
BEFORE YOU
JETTISONED THE POD?
YES, SIR, THERE WAS.
PLEASE TELL US
ABOUT IT.
FIRSTLY, I AM AT A LOSS
TO EXPLAIN THE ERRORS
IN THE EXTRACT
FROM THE COMPUTER LOG.
WE WERE IN AN ION STORM.
EVERYONE HERE IN THIS COURT
KNOWS THE DANGERS INVOLVED.
I WAS IN COMMAND.
THE DECISIONS WERE MINE,
NO ONE ELSE'S.
CHARGES OF MALICE
HAVE BEEN RAISED.
THERE WAS NO MALICE.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER FINNEY
WAS A MEMBER OF MY CREW,
AND THAT'S EXACTLY THE WAY
HE WAS TREATED.
IT HAS BEEN SUGGESTED THAT
I PANICKED ON THE BRIDGE
AND JETTISONED THE ION POD
PREMATURELY.
THAT IS NOT SO.
YOU HAVE HEARD SOME OF THE
DETAILS OF MY RECORD.
THIS WAS NOT
MY FIRST CRISIS.
IT WAS ONE OF MANY.
DURING IT, I DID
WHAT MY EXPERIENCE
AND TRAINING
REQUIRED ME TO DO.
I TOOK THE PROPER STEPS
IN THE PROPER ORDER.
I DID EXACTLY
WHAT HAD TO BE DONE
EXACTLY WHEN IT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN DONE.
YOU DID
THE RIGHT THING,
BUT WOULD YOU
DO IT AGAIN?
GIVEN THE SAME
CIRCUMSTANCES...
I WOULD DO THE SAME THING
WITHOUT HESITATION...
BECAUSE THE STEPS I TOOK
IN THE ORDER I TOOK THEM
WERE ABSOLUTELY NECESSARY
IF I WERE TO SAVE MY SHIP.
AND NOTHING...
IS MORE IMPORTANT
THAN MY SHIP.
YOUR WITNESS, MISS SHAW.
THE PROSECUTION
DOES NOT WISH
TO DISHONOR THIS MAN,
BUT FACTS ARE FACTS.
I MUST INVITE
THE ATTENTION
OF THE COURT
AND CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THIS VISUAL EXTRACT
FROM THE ENTERPRISE
COMPUTER LOG.
PLAYBACK.
WHAT YOU ARE
ABOUT TO SEE
IS PRECISELY
WHAT TOOK PLACE
ON THE ENTERPRISE
BRIDGE
DURING THE ION STORM.
METEOROLOGY REPORTS
ION STORM UPCOMING,
CAPTAIN.
WE'LL NEED SOMEBODY
IN THE POD FOR READINGS,
MR. SPOCK.
MR. FINNEY IS TOP
OF DUTY ROSTER, CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT.
ATTENTION,
COMMANDER FINNEY,
REPORT TO POD
FOR READING
ON ION SLATES.
[FINNEY]
MESSAGE RECEIVED.
OFFICER POSTED,
CAPTAIN.
STAND BY ON ALERT STATUS,
MR. SPOCK.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
APPROACHING
ION STORM, SIR.
WARP FACTOR 1,
MR. HANSON.
WARP 1, SIR.
REVERSE.
STOP.
GO FORWARD WITH
MAGNIFICATION ON THE PANEL.
FREEZE THAT.
CAPTAIN KIRK IS NOW
SIGNALING A YELLOW ALERT.
GO FORWARD,
NORMAL VIEW.
CALL FROM
THE POD, SIR.
TIE IN.
FINNEY HERE,
CAPTAIN.
ION READINGS
IN PROGRESS.
MAKE IT FAST, BEN.
I MAY HAVE TO GO
TO RED ALERT.
AFFIRMATIVE.
HOLD YOUR COURSE,
MR. HANSON.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
NATURAL VIBRATIONS,
FORCE 2, CAPTAIN.
FORCE 3.
ENGINEERING,
THEN ION POD.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
ENGINEERING.
1/3 MORE THRUST.
WORKING.
[FINNEY]
ION POD.
STAND BY TO GET OUT
OF THERE, BEN.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
FORCE 5, SIR.
STEADY AS SHE GOES,
MR. HANSON.
FREEZE THAT!
IF THE COURT
WILL NOTICE,
THE LOG
PLAINLY SHOWS
THE DEFENDANT'S
FINGER
PRESSING
THE JETTISON BUTTON.
THE CONDITION SIGNAL
READS YELLOW ALERT,
NOT RED ALERT,
BUT SIMPLY YELLOW
ALERT.
WHEN THE POD
CONTAINING
LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY
WAS JETTISONED,
THE EMERGENCY
DID NOT
AS YET EXIST.
BUT THAT'S NOT
THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2949.9.
THE EVIDENCE PRESENTED
BY THE VISUAL PLAYBACK
TO MY GENERAL
COURT-MARTIAL
WAS DAMNING.
I SUSPECT
EVEN MY ATTORNEY
HAS BEGUN TO DOUBT ME.
COMPUTERS
DON'T LIE.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT I DID?
I'M SUGGESTING
THAT MAYBE YOU DID
HAVE A LAPSE.
IT WAS POSSIBLE,
YOU KNOW,
WITH THE STRAIN
YOU WERE UNDER.
THERE'S STILL TIME
TO CHANGE OUR PLEA.
I COULD
GET YOU OFF.
TWO DAYS AGO,
I WOULD'VE STAKED
ANYTHING
ON MY JUDGMENT.
YOU DID. YOUR
PROFESSIONAL CAREER.
I SPENT MY WHOLE LIFE
TRAINING FOR DECISIONS
JUST LIKE THAT ONE.
MY WHOLE LIFE.
IS IT POSSIBLE THAT
WHEN THE MOMENT CAME, I...
NO.
I KNOW WHAT I DID.
YOU CAN PULL OUT
IF YOU WANT TO.
THERE'S NO PLACE
TO GO,
EXCEPT BACK TO
COURT AND HEAR
THE VERDICT.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, I'VE
RUN A COMPLETE
MEGALYTE SURVEY
ON THE COMPUTER.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT
YOU FOUND-- NOTHING,
RIGHT?
YOU SOUND BITTER,
CAPTAIN.
NOT BITTER ENOUGH
TO FORGET TO THANK
YOU FOR YOUR EFFORTS.
FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS?
NO. IT'S NOT
ALL BAD, MR. SPOCK.
WHO KNOWS? YOU MAY BE
ABLE TO BEAT YOUR NEXT
CAPTAIN AT CHESS.
KIRK OUT.
CHESS.
JAME.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY'S
DAUGHTER.
MR. COGLEY, WE'VE
GOT TO STOP THIS.
MAKE HIM TAKE
A GROUND ASSIGNMENT.
I REALIZE IT WASN'T
HIS FAULT.
I WON'T MAKE
ANY TROUBLE.
MAKE HIM CHANGE
HIS PLEA.
IT'S TOO LATE
FOR THAT, JAME,
BUT I'M GLAD YOU DON'T
BLAME ME ANYMORE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED.
I WAS JUST SO UPSET
THAT NIGHT.
I'M SORRY.
DON'T SAY ANY MORE.
BUT I HAVE TO.
I NEVER REALIZED
HOW CLOSE YOU
AND DAD HAD BEEN
UNTIL I READ
THROUGH SOME OF THE
PAPERS HE WROTE,
LETTERS TO MOTHER
AND ME.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
I EVER COULD'VE
THOUGHT THAT YOU...
MR. COGLEY,
RUINING JIM
WON'T CHANGE
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
THAT'S VERY COMMENDABLE,
MISS FINNEY,
BUT MOST UNUSUAL.
AFTER ALL,
CAPTAIN KIRK IS ACCUSED
OF CAUSING
YOUR FATHER'S DEATH,
AND THE EVIDENCE
WOULD INDICATE HIS GUILT.
I WAS JUST
THINKING OF JIM.
I KNOW,
AND I THANK YOU.
I HAVE TO GO AND CHANGE.
YOU READY?
NO, BUT I MAY
BE GETTING READY.
BISHOP HALF LEVEL RIGHT.
WELL, I HAD TO SEE IT
TO BELIEVE IT.
EXPLAIN.
THEY'RE ABOUT
TO LOP OFF
THE CAPTAIN'S
PROFESSIONAL HEAD,
AND YOU'RE SITTING
HERE PLAYING CHESS
WITH THE COMPUTER.
THAT IS TRUE.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU'RE THE MOST
COLD-BLOODED MAN
I'VE EVER KNOWN.
WHY, THANK YOU,
DOCTOR.
I'VE JUST WON
MY FOURTH GAME.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
OBSERVE
FOR YOURSELF.
ROOK TO KING'S
PAWN 4.
BISHOP
HALF LEVEL RIGHT.
NOW, THIS IS
THE COMPUTER'S MOVE.
AND NOW MINE.
CHECKMATE.
MECHANICALLY, THE
COMPUTER IS FLAWLESS.
THEREFORE, LOGICALLY,
ITS REPORT
OF THE CAPTAIN'S GUILT
IS INFALLIBLE.
I COULD NOT
ACCEPT THAT, HOWEVER.
SO YOU TESTED
THE PROGRAM BANK.
EXACTLY.
I PROGRAMMED IT
MYSELF FOR CHESS
SOME MONTHS AGO.
THE BEST
I SHOULD'VE BEEN
ABLE TO OBTAIN
WAS A DRAW.
WELL, WHY ARE YOU
JUST SITTING THERE?
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
STAND BY. WE'RE
BEAMING DOWN.
[RINGING BELL]
COURT IS NOW
IN SESSION.
THE BOARD WILL
ENTERTAIN MOTIONS
BEFORE DELIVERING
ITS VERDICT.
COUNSEL
FOR THE PROSECUTION?
SIR, THE PROSECUTION
RESTS.
COUNSEL
FOR THE DEFENSE?
SIR...
THE DEFENSE RESTS.
[DOOR OPENS]
MR. COGLEY.
MR. COGLEY!
SIR,
SOME NEW EVIDENCE
HAS JUST
BEEN BROUGHT
TO MY ATTENTION,
AND I'D LIKE
TO ASK THE COURT--
OBJECTION!
COUNSEL FOR
THE DEFENSE HAS
RESTED HIS CASE.
OF WHAT NATURE
IS THIS EVIDENCE?
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
I HAVE TO SHOW YOU,
SIR.
MR. COGLEY
IS WELL-KNOWN
FOR HIS THEATRICS.
IS SAVING
AN INNOCENT MAN'S
CAREER A THEATRIC?
COUNSELS WILL KINDLY
DIRECT THEIR REMARKS
TO THE BENCH.
I'D BE DELIGHTED
TO, SIR,
NOW THAT I'VE GOT
SOMETHING HUMAN
TO TALK ABOUT.
RIGHTS, SIR,
HUMAN RIGHTS--
THE BIBLE, THE CODE
OF HAMMURABI
AND OF JUSTINIAN,
MAGNA CARTA,
THE CONSTITUTION
OF THE UNITED
STATES,
FUNDAMENTAL
DECLARATIONS
OF THE MARTIAN
COLONIES.
THE STATUTES
OF ALPHA 3--
GENTLEMEN,
THESE DOCUMENTS
ALL SPEAK OF RIGHTS.
RIGHTS
OF THE ACCUSED
TO A TRIAL
BY HIS PEERS,
TO BE REPRESENTED
BY COUNSEL,
THE RIGHTS OF
CROSS-EXAMINATION,
BUT
MOST IMPORTANTLY,
THE RIGHT
TO BE CONFRONTED
BY THE WITNESSES
AGAINST HIM--
A RIGHT TO
WHICH MY CLIENT
HAS BEEN DENIED.
YOUR HONOR,
THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
WE PRODUCED
THE WITNESSES IN COURT.
MY LEARNED OPPONENT
HAD THE OPPORTUNITY
TO SEE THEM,
CROSS-EXAMINE THEM--
ALL BUT ONE!
THE MOST
DEVASTATING WITNESS
AGAINST MY CLIENT
IS NOT A HUMAN BEING.
IT'S A MACHINE,
AN INFORMATION
SYSTEM--
THE COMPUTER LOG
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
AND I ASK THIS COURT
ADJOURN AND RECONVENE
ABOARD THAT VESSEL.
I PROTEST,
YOUR HONOR.
AND I REPEAT,
I SPEAK OF RIGHTS.
A MACHINE HAS NONE.
A MAN MUST.
MY CLIENT HAS THE RIGHT
TO FACE HIS ACCUSER,
AND IF YOU DO NOT
GRANT HIM THAT RIGHT,
YOU HAVE BROUGHT US DOWN
TO THE LEVEL
OF THE MACHINE.
INDEED, YOU HAVE ELEVATED
THAT MACHINE ABOVE US.
I ASK THAT MY MOTION
BE GRANTED,
AND MORE
THAN THAT, GENTLEMEN,
IN THE NAME
OF HUMANITY,
FADING IN THE SHADOW
OF THE MACHINE,
I DEMAND IT.
I DEMAND IT!
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 2950.1.
AFTER DUE
CONSIDERATION,
THE GENERAL COURT-MARTIAL
HAS RECONVENED
ON BOARD THE ENTERPRISE.
HOW MANY GAMES OF CHESS
DID YOU WIN
FROM THE COMPUTER,
MR. SPOCK?
FIVE IN ALL.
MAY THAT BE
CONSIDERED UNUSUAL?
AFFIRMATIVE.
WHY?
I PERSONALLY
PROGRAMMED THE
COMPUTER FOR CHESS
MONTHS AGO.
I GAVE THE MACHINE
AN UNDERSTANDING
OF THE GAME
EQUAL TO MY OWN.
THE COMPUTER CANNOT
MAKE AN ERROR.
AND ASSUMING THAT
I DO NOT EITHER,
THE BEST THAT COULD
NORMALLY
BE HOPED FOR
WOULD BE STALEMATE
AFTER STALEMATE,
AND YET I BEAT
THE MACHINE
FIVE TIMES.
SOMEONE, EITHER
ACCIDENTALLY
OR DELIBERATELY,
ADJUSTED
THE PROGRAMMING
AND, THEREFORE,
THE MEMORY BANKS
OF THAT COMPUTER.
COULD THAT HAVE HAD AN EFFECT ON
THE VISUAL PLAYBACK WE SAW?
OBJECT!
THE WITNESS WOULD BE
MAKING A CONCLUSION.
SUSTAINED.
HYPOTHETICALLY,
MR. SPOCK.
MISS SHAW,
IF WHAT YOU SUGGEST
HAD BEEN DONE,
IT WOULD BE BEYOND
THE CAPABILITIES
OF MOST MEN.
IS THAT TRUE?
AFFIRMATIVE.
WHAT MAN ABOARD SHIP
WOULD IT NOT
BE BEYOND?
THE CAPTAIN,
MYSELF,
AND THE RECORDS
OFFICER.
MM-HMM.
AND AT THE MOMENT,
YOU HAVE
NO RECORDS OFFICER.
AFFIRMATIVE.
UNTIL HE WAS LOST,
OUR RECORDS OFFICER
WAS LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER FINNEY.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
WILL YOU TELL
THE STEPS YOU TOOK
TO FIND MR. FINNEY
AFTER THE STORM?
I INSTITUTED
A PHASE 1 SEARCH.
DESCRIBE
IT'S A PAINSTAKING,
THOROUGH ATTEMPT
IN AND AROUND
THE SHIP
TO FIND A MAN WHO'S
PRESUMABLY INJURED
AND UNABLE
TO RESPOND.
IT PRESUPPOSES,
DOES IT NOT,
THAT A MAN WISHES
TO BE FOUND?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
IF YOU START
A SEARCH
FOR A MAN,
YOU ASSUME, DON'T YOU,
THAT HE WANTS
TO BE FOUND?
HE'S NOT HIDING?
YES.
ON A SHIP
OF THIS SIZE,
COULD A MAN
EVADE SUCH A SEARCH?
POSSIBLY.
GENTLEMEN,
I SUBMIT TO YOU
THAT LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER BEN FINNEY
IS NOT DEAD.
MR. COGLEY, YOUR
WAITING FOR PROOF
OF THE EXTRAORDINARY
STATEMENT YOU MADE
IN THE BRIEFING ROOM.
YOU SHALL HAVE IT,
BUT FIRST I NEED THE
COOPERATION OF THIS COURT
IN CONDUCTING
AN EXPERIMENT.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
GENTLEMEN,
FOR THE PURPOSES
OF THIS EXPERIMENT,
IT'LL BE NECESSARY
FOR ALL PERSONNEL,
EXCEPT FOR MEMBERS
OF THE COURT AND
THE COMMAND CREW,
TO LEAVE THE SHIP.
I'M ORDERING
ALL OTHERS TO REPORT
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
INCLUDING MYSELF, SIR.
THIS COURT IS BY
NO MEANS ADJOURNED,
MR. COGLEY.
I HAVE AN ERRAND ASHORE
OF VITAL IMPORTANCE TO
THE PURPOSE OF THIS COURT,
AND I WILL RETURN.
VERY WELL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU
MAINTAINING
AN ENGINE CREW
ABOARD?
OUR IMPULSE ENGINES
HAVE BEEN SHUT DOWN.
WE'LL MAINTAIN ORBIT
BY MOMENTUM.
AND WHEN THE ORBIT
BEGINS TO DECAY?
WE HOPE TO BE FINISHED
LONG BEFORE THAT.
READY, MR. SPOCK?
AFFIRMATIVE,
CAPTAIN.
GENTLEMEN,
THIS COMPUTER
HAS AN AUDITORY
SENSOR.
IT CAN, IN EFFECT,
HEAR SOUNDS.
BY INSTALLING
A BOOSTER,
WE CAN INCREASE
THAT CAPABILITY
ON THE ORDER OF
1 TO THE 4th POWER.
THE COMPUTER
SHOULD BE ABLE TO
BRING US EVERY SOUND
OCCURRING
ON THE SHIP.
ALL PERSONNEL
HAVE LEFT THE SHIP
AS ORDERED, SIR.
DR. McCOY?
ALL RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK.
[LOUD BEATING]
TURN IT DOWN
A LITTLE.
[VOLUME DECREASES]
GENTLEMEN, THAT SOUND
IS CAUSED BY THE HEARTBEATS
OF ALL THE PEOPLE
ON BOARD THE SHIP.
DR. McCOY WILL USE
THIS WHITE SOUND DEVICE
TO MASK OUT
EACH PERSON'S HEARTBEAT
SO THAT IT WILL BE
ELIMINATED
FROM THE SOUNDS
WE'RE HEARING.
FIRST, THE CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK.
AND LASTLY, MYSELF.
THAT'S ALL OF US,
EXCEPT FOR THE CREWMAN
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
MR. SPOCK, ELIMINATE
HIS HEARTBEAT.
[HEARTBEAT CONTINUES]
THAT ACCOUNTS
FOR EVERYONE.
[SINGLE HEART BEATS]
FINNEY.
LOCALIZE THAT.
"B" DECK.
IN OR NEAR
ENGINEERING.
SEAL OFF "B" DECK,
SECTIONS 18-Y
THROUGH 23-D.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[BEEP]
SO FINNEY IS ALIVE.
IT WOULD SEEM SO.
COMMODORE, THIS IS
MY PROBLEM.
I WOULD APPRECIATE IT IF
NO ONE LEFT THE BRIDGE.
SAM COGLEY HAD GONE ASHORE
TO BRING JAME FINNEY
ON BOARD.
WE BOTH FELT
THAT JAME'S PRESENCE
WOULD MAKE FINNEY
EASIER TO HANDLE
IN THE EVENT FINNEY
REALLY WERE ALIVE.
BEN.
[KIRK]
BEN FINNEY.
MR. SPOCK,
ENCOUNTERING
VARIANTS.
COMPENSATE.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
THE ORBIT IS
BEGINNING TO DECAY.
BEN, WHERE ARE YOU?
HELLO, CAPTAIN!
NOTHING TO SAY, CAPTAIN?
I'M GLAD
YOU'RE ALIVE.
YOU MEAN
YOU'RE RELIEVED
BECAUSE YOU THINK
YOUR CAREER
IS SAVED.
WELL, YOU'RE WRONG.
BEN!
BEN, IT'S NOT
TOO LATE.
WE CAN HELP YOU.
LIKE YOU HELPED ME
ALL ALONG, KEPT ME DOWN,
ROBBED ME
OF MY OWN COMMAND?
I'M A GOOD OFFICER.
AS GOOD AS YOU.
I'VE WATCHED YOU
FOR YEARS.
THE GREAT CAPTAIN KIRK.
THEY TOLD YOU
TO DO IT TO ME.
YOU ALL CONSPIRED
AGAINST ME.
YOU RUINED ME,
BUT YOU WON'T
DO IT ANYMORE.
UHH.
PUT THE PHASER
DOWN, BEN.
OH, I WOULDN'T
KILL YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOUR OWN DEATH WOULD
MEAN TOO
LITTLE TO YOU,
BUT YOUR SHIP--
WHAT ABOUT MY SHIP?
IT'S DEAD.
I'VE KILLED IT.
I TAPPED OUT
YOUR PRIMARY
ENERGY CIRCUITS.
MR. SPOCK, WHAT'S
OUR ORBIT STATUS?
DECAYING, CAPTAIN.
VARIANTS
AT SECOND LEVEL
DEPRECIATING
UNUSUALLY FAST.
YOU'RE OUT OF POWER.
I KNOW
THIS SHIP, TOO.
THE ENTERPRISE
SHOULD'VE BEEN MINE.
YOU KEPT ME
FROM IT.
BEN...
WHY KILL
INNOCENT PEOPLE?
INNOCENT?
HA HA HA!
OFFICERS AND GENTLEMEN,
CAPTAINS ALL,
EXCEPT FOR FINNEY
AND HIS ONE MISTAKE
A LONG TIME AGO,
BUT THEY
DON'T FORGET.
I LOGGED THE MISTAKE,
BEN. BLAME ME, NOT THEM.
BUT THEY ARE TO BLAME.
ALL OF THEM.
I WAS A GOOD OFFICER.
I REALLY WAS.
I LOVED THE SERVICE
MORE THAN ANY MAN
EVER DID.
MR. SPOCK,
WE'RE RUNNING OUT
OF TIME.
GENTLEMEN, IF YOU'LL
PLEASE HURRY TO THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM--
MR. SPOCK, THE COURT
HAS NOT YET REACHED
A VERDICT.
WE WILL HEAR
THIS WITNESS OUT.
VERY WELL, SIR.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
YOU CAN BE HELPED,
BUT IF YOU KILL
ALL THOSE PEOPLE--
WHY SHOULDN'T I?
THEY KILLED ME,
DIDN'T THEY?
IT'S A FAIR TRADE.
IS JAME INCLUDED
IN THAT DEAL?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
SHE'S ON BOARD
BY NOW.
YES. SHE'S ON BOARD.
WHY DID YOU DO THAT?
WHY DID YOU BRING
HER HERE?
I'LL KILL YOU!
BEATEN AND SOBBING,
FINNEY TOLD ME WHERE
HE HAD SABOTAGED
THE PRIME ENERGY CIRCUITS.
THE DAMAGE HE HAD CAUSED
WAS CONSIDERABLE,
BUT NOT IRREPARABLE.
WITH LUCK,
I WOULD BE ABLE TO
EFFECT REPAIRS
BEFORE OUR ORBIT
DECAYED COMPLETELY.
POWER RETURNING,
MR. SPOCK.
UP 14 POINTS
AND RISING.
ACTIVATE PORT
IMPULSE ENGINES.
1/3 POWER.
VARIANTS FADING.
ORBIT
STABILIZING.
ALL SECURE, SIR.
UNLESS
THE PROSECUTION
HAS AN OBJECTION,
I RULE THIS COURT
TO BE DISMISSED.
ABSOLUTELY
NO OBJECTION, SIR.
HOW LONG WILL IT BE
THIS TIME BEFORE
I SEE YOU AGAIN?
AT THE RISK
OF SOUNDING
LIKE A MYSTIC,
THAT DEPENDS
ON THE STARS.
SAM COGLEY ASKED
ME TO GIVE YOU
SOMETHING SPECIAL.
IT'S NOT A FIRST
EDITION OR ANYTHING--
JUST A BOOK.
SAM SAYS THAT
MAKES IT SPECIAL,
THOUGH.
I DIDN'T HAVE
MUCH OF A CHANCE
TO THANK HIM.
HE'S BUSY
ON A CASE.
HE'S DEFENDING
BEN FINNEY.
HE SAYS HE'LL WIN.
I WOULDN'T BE
A BIT SURPRISED.
DO YOU THINK
IT WOULD CAUSE
A COMPLETE BREAKDOWN
OF DISCIPLINE
IF A LOWLY LIEUTENANT
KISSED A STARSHIP CAPTAIN
ON THE BRIDGE
OF HIS SHIP?
LET'S TRY.
SEE? NO CHANGE.
DISCIPLINE
GOES ON.
AND SO MUST
THE ENTERPRISE.
GOODBYE, JIM.
GOODBYE, AREEL.
BETTER LUCK
NEXT TIME.
I HAD PRETTY GOOD LUCK
THIS TIME.
I LOST, DIDN'T I?
SHE'S A VERY GOOD LAWYER.
OBVIOUSLY.
INDEED SHE IS.