O'NEIL,
WE'VE GOT TO KEEP GOING.
COME ON. GET UP.
IT'S NO USE.
THEY'RE EVERYWHERE.
CAPTAIN GAVE US
AN ORDER.
WE'VE GOT TO FIND
SOME CLUE.
IT'S NO USE, MR. SULU.
LOOK.
THERE'S ONE OF THEM.
THERE'S ANOTHER ONE.
SCOUTING PARTY
TO ENTERPRISE--
COME IN.
WHAT IS IT, MR. SULU?
CAPTAIN,
BEAM US UP QUICK.
EMERGENCY.
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
LOCK ONTO SULU AND O'NEIL.
BEAM UP IMMEDIATELY.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE
A RUN FOR IT.
WE CAN'T JUST
STAND HERE.
MR. O'NEIL, STAND TIGHT.
THEY'LL BEAM US UP IN A MINUTE.
RUN, I TELL YOU.
WE'VE GOT TO GET
OUT OF HERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE CAPABLE OF.
O'NEIL!
[ZAP]
SULU, WHAT IS IT?
WHERE'S LIEUTENANT O'NEIL?
WHAT?
WHO?
LIEUTENANT O'NEIL--
WHERE IS HE?
YOU...
YOU'RE NOT
OF THE BODY.
DR. McCOY.
DR. McCOY,
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
QUICKLY.
YOU, YOU DID IT.
THEY KNEW WE WERE ARCHONS.
THESE ARE THE CLOTHES
THEY WEAR, NOT THESE.
SULU, TAKE IT EASY.
LANDRU.
SIT DOWN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
THEY'RE
THE SWEETEST...
FRIENDLIEST PEOPLE
IN THE UNIVERSE.
IT'S PARADISE,
MY FRIEND.
PARADISE.
LIEUTENANT O'NEIL--
WHERE IS HE?
PARADISE.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3156.2--
WHILE ORBITING
PLANET BETA 3
TRYING TO FIND SOME TRACE
OF THE STARSHIP ARCHON
THAT DISAPPEARED HERE
A HUNDRED YEARS AGO,
A SEARCH PARTY CONSISTING
OF TWO ENTERPRISE OFFICERS
WERE SENT
TO THE PLANET BELOW.
MR. SULU HAS RETURNED,
BUT IN A HIGHLY AGITATED
MENTAL STATE.
HIS CONDITION REQUIRES
I BEAM DOWN
WITH AN ADDITIONAL
SEARCH DETAIL.
MATERIALIZATION COMPLETED.
KIRK OUT.
ODD.
THE EXPRESSION
ON THAT MAN'S FACE,
THE MINDLESSNESS,
VACANT CONTENTMENT.
LIKE SULU.
IF EVERYBODY ON THIS PLANET
IS LIKE HIM...
LET'S GO.
JOY TO YOU, FRIENDS.
JOY TO YOU.
YOU BE STRANGERS.
COME FOR THE FESTIVAL,
ARE YOU?
YES.
GOT A PLACE
TO SLEEP IT OFF YET?
GO AROUND TO REGER'S HOUSE.
HE'S GOT ROOMS...
BUT YOU'LL HAVE TO HURRY.
IT'S ALMOST THE RED HOUR.
THIS, UH, FESTIVAL,
IT STARTS AT 6:00?
TULA,
THESE FOLKS COME
FOR THE FESTIVAL.
YOUR DADDY
CAN PUT THEM UP,
CAN'T HE?
YOU'RE FROM THE VALLEY?
WE'VE, UH,
JUST ARRIVED.
MY FATHER WILL BE GLAD
TO PUT YOU UP, THOUGH.
IT'S RIGHT OVER THERE.
[CLOCK BELL TOLLS]
AAH!
TULA, COME!
[SHOUTING]
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
I'M SORRY TO BREAK
IN ON YOU LIKE THIS.
WE DIDN'T EXPECT
THAT KIND OF A WELCOME.
WELCOME?
YOU ARE STRANGERS?
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE...FROM THE VALLEY.
YOU CAME
FOR THE FESTIVAL?
YES.
AND HOW
COME YOU HERE?
ARE YOU REGER?
YES.
YOU HAVE A DAUGHTER
NAMED TULA?
YES.
WELL, YOU BETTER DO SOMETHING.
SHE'S OUTSIDE.
I KNOW.
IT'S FESTIVAL.
IT'S THE WILL
OF LANDRU.
REGER, THESE
ARE YOUNG MEN.
THEY ARE NOT
OLD ENOUGH
TO BE EXCUSED.
THEY'RE VISITORS.
WELL, HAVE THEY
NO LAWGIVERS
IN THE VALLEY?
WHY BE THEY NOT
AT THE FESTIVAL?
WE HEARD THAT YOU MIGHT
HAVE ROOMS FOR US.
THERE.
YOU SEE, HACOM?
THEY'VE MERELY COME
LOOKING FOR A PLACE
TO REST AFTERWARDS.
THE RED HOUR
HAS ALREADY STRUCK.
HACOM, THESE BE STRANGERS.
THE VALLEY
HAS DIFFERENT WAYS.
DO YOU SAY
THAT LANDRU
IS NOT EVERYWHERE?
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
IT'S SIMPLY THAT THEY
MAY HAVE DIFFERENT WAYS.
THEY'VE COME LOOKING
FOR SHELTER.
CAN I TURN THEM AWAY?
COME, PLEASE.
BUT THE GIRL, OUT THERE?
SHE IS IN FESTIVAL,
AS YOU SHOULD BE.
COME, PLEASE. HURRY.
THE LAWGIVERS
SHOULD KNOW.
SURELY, HACOM,
THEY ALREADY KNOW.
ARE THEY NOT
INFALLIBLE?
YOU MOCK THEM!
YOU MOCK
THE LAWGIVERS.
THAT THE STRANGERS
ARE NOT OF THE BODY,
YOU WILL SEE.
BUT, HACOM...
YOU CAN RETURN HERE
AT THE CLOSE OF THE FESTIVAL.
IT'S QUIET.
YOU'LL HAVE NEED OF REST.
WE HAVE NO PLANS TO
ATTEND THE FESTIVAL,
SIR.
[CROWD SHOUTING
AND GLASS BREAKING]
THE HOUR HAS STRUCK.
YOU CAN HEAR.
I'D LIKE TO HEAR MORE ABOUT
THIS FESTIVAL...AND LANDRU.
LANDRU?
YOU ASK...
WELL, YOU'RE STRANGE.
YOU SCORN FESTIVAL?
ARE YOU...
WHAT ABOUT LANDRU?
FESTIVAL!
LANDRU.
MY GUESS IS
WE HAVE UNTIL MORNING.
LET'S PUT THE TIME
TO GOOD USE.
DOCTOR,
DO ATMOSPHERIC READINGS
TO DETERMINE WHETHER
THERE'S ANYTHING
IN THE AIR TO ACCOUNT
FOR ALL THIS.
MR. LINDSTROM, CORRELATE
ALL THAT YOU'VE SEEN
WITH ANY OTHER SOCIOLOGICAL
PARALLELS, IF ANY.
MR. SPOCK...
YOU AND I HAVE
SOME SERIOUS
THINKING TO DO.
WHEN WE LEAVE HERE
TOMORROW MORNING,
I WANT TO HAVE
A PLAN OF ACTION.
[BELL TOLLING]
SPOCK. SPOCK. LINDSTROM.
DOC.
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
NO. NOW IT'S OVER.
NO, NO, IT'S ALL OVER NOW.
IT'S ALL OVER NOW, TULA.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT. QUIET.
EXCUSE ME.
COME ON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL OVER.
HE'LL GIVE HER A SHOT.
IT'LL CALM HER DOWN.
TRUST US.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN TRY
TO BRING HER BACK.
WHAT KIND OF FATHER
ARE YOU?
IT'S LANDRU'S WILL.
WHAT ABOUT LANDRU?
WHO IS HE?
IT IS TRUE THEN.
YOU DID NOT ATTEND
THE FESTIVAL
LAST NIGHT.
NO.
THEN YOU'RE NOT
OF THE BODY.
YOU COULDN'T BE.
SHE'S ASLEEP.
ARE YOU...
ARE YOU ARCHONS?
WHAT IF WE ARE?
IT WAS SAID
MORE WOULD FOLLOW.
IF YOU ARE INDEED--
WE MUST HIDE THEM.
QUICKLY. THE LAWGIVERS.
WE CAN TAKE CARE
OF OURSELVES.
LANDRU WILL KNOW.
HE WILL COME.
HE IS THE ONE.
HE MOCKED THE LAWGIVERS.
I HEARD HIM.
NO, HACOM.
IT WAS A JEST.
THE OTHERS,
THEY WERE HERE,
BUT THEY SCORNED
THE FESTIVAL.
I SAW IT.
TAMAR, STAND CLEAR.
I HEAR...
AND OBEY THE VOICE
OF LANDRU.
YOU ATTACKED
THE BODY.
YOU HAVE
HEARD THE WORD
AND DISOBEYED.
YOU WILL BE
ABSORBED.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
ABSORBED?
THERE. YOU SEE?
NOT OF THE BODY.
YOU WILL BE
ABSORBED.
THE GOOD IS ALL.
LANDRU
IS GENTLE.
YOU WILL COME.
WE'RE NOT GOING
ANYWHERE.
IT IS THE LAW.
YOU MUST COME.
I SAID WE'RE NOT
GOING ANYWHERE.
EVIDENTLY THEY'RE NOT
PREPARED TO DEAL
WITH OUTRIGHT DISOBEDIENCE.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
EVERYTHING WE'VE
SEEN HERE SO FAR
SEEMS
TO INDICATE SOME
SORT OF COMPULSIVE,
INVOLUNTARY STIMULUS
TO ACTION.
YOUR ANALYSIS SEEMS LOGICAL.
IT IS CLEAR
THAT YOU SIMPLY
DID NOT UNDERSTAND.
I WILL REPHRASE.
YOU ARE ORDERED
TO ACCOMPANY US
TO THE ABSORPTION
CHAMBERS.
WHY DID YOU KILL THAT MAN?
OUT OF ORDER.
YOU WILL OBEY.
IT IS THE WORD
OF LANDRU.
YOU TELL LANDRU
THAT WE'LL COME
IN OUR OWN TIME
AND THAT WE'LL SPEAK
TO HIM.
YOU CANNOT.
IT IS LANDRU.
LANDRU.
FASCINATING.
THIS IS MERELY
A HOLLOW TUBE, CAPTAIN.
NO MECHANISM.
THEY'RE COMMUNING.
WE HAVE TIME. COME WITH ME.
WHERE TO?
TO A PLACE I KNOW.
YOU'LL BE SAFE THERE.
BUT WE MUST HURRY.
LANDRU WILL COME.
QUITE A FESTIVAL
THEY HAD.
PEACE.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF ALL THIS?
TOTALLY ILLOGICAL.
YESTERDAY WITHOUT APPARENT
CAUSE OR REASON,
THEY WROUGHT TOTAL HAVOC,
YET TODAY, NOW--
NOW THEY'RE BACK
TO NORMAL.
MORNING, FRIENDS.
GOOD MORNING, BILAR.
YOUR DAUGHTER--
THAT'S THE MAN!
NO, IT WASN'T BILAR.
IT WAS LANDRU.
LET'S HURRY.
WE HAVEN'T MUCH TIME.
IT'S TOO LATE. LOOK.
WHAT IS IT?
LANDRU--
HE'S SUMMONING THE BODY.
TELEPATHY, CAPTAIN.
PHASERS ON STUN.
WHICH WAY, REGER?
PERHAPS THROUGH THERE,
BUT LANDRU...
WE'LL HANDLE LANDRU.
JUST GET US
OUT OF THIS.
I DON'T WANT
TO HURT THEM.
WARN THEM BACK.
THEY'RE IN THE BODY.
IT'S LANDRU.
PHASERS ON STUN,
WIDE FIELD. FIRE.
FIRE.
SECURITY.
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT O'NEIL.
HE'S ONE OF OUR MEN.
NOT ANYMORE.
HE'S BEEN ABSORBED.
BRING HIM ALONG.
BUT I TELL YOU,
HE'S ONE OF THEM.
WHEN HE WAKES, LANDRU
WILL FIND US THROUGH HIM.
LEAVE HIM THERE.
HE'S OUR ENEMY.
HE'S BEEN ABSORBED.
CAPTAIN, NOW THAT WE'VE
GOT LIEUTENANT O'NEIL,
LET'S BEAM UP
OUT OF HERE.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO THE ARCHONS.
WHICH WAY?
BRING HIM ALONG.
PUT HIM OVER THERE.
A LIGHTING PANEL.
AMAZING
IN THIS CULTURE.
COMES FROM A TIME
BEFORE LANDRU.
BEFORE LANDRU?
HOW LONG AGO WAS THAT?
NOBODY KNOWS
POSITIVELY.
SOME SAY AS LONG AGO
AS 6,000 YEARS.
CAPTAIN, IT TOOK
A VERY ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
TO CONSTRUCT A DEVICE
LIKE THIS--
INCONSISTENT
WITH THIS ENVIRONMENT--
BUT NOT INCONSISTENT
WITH WHAT WE'VE SEEN.
SECURITY.
THOSE STAFFS,
HOLLOW TUBES--
ANTENNAE, SOME SORT
OF BROADCAST POWER.
WHAT IS IT, MR. SPOCK?
MOSTLY STRONG
POWER GENERATIONS, CAPTAIN,
NEAR HERE, BUT RADIATING
IN ALL DIRECTIONS.
HE'LL BE COMING AROUND
SOON, CAPTAIN.
HE MUST NOT.
HE'S BEEN ABSORBED.
ABSORBED?
THE BODY ABSORBS
ITS ENEMIES.
IT ONLY KILLS
WHEN IT HAS TO.
WHEN THE FIRST
ARCHONS CAME,
THEY WERE FREE,
OUT OF CONTROL,
OPPOSING THE WILL
OF LANDRU.
MANY WERE KILLED,
MANY MORE WERE ABSORBED.
WHEN HE REGAINS
CONSCIOUSNESS,
LANDRU WILL FIND US
THROUGH HIM,
AND IF
THE OTHERS COME--
WHAT OTHERS?
THOSE LIKE YOU AND ME,
WHO RESIST LANDRU.
AN UNDERGROUND?
HOW ARE YOU ORGANIZED?
IN THREES--
MYSELF,
TAMAR, WHO'S DEAD NOW,
AND ONE OTHER.
WHO?
I DON'T KNOW.
TAMAR WAS MY CONTACT.
GIVE ME
A DECISION, CAPTAIN.
HE'S COMING OUT OF IT.
HE MUST NOT
REGAIN CONSCIOUSNESS.
HE'LL DESTROY US ALL.
HE'S OF THE BODY.
GIVE HIM A SHOT.
KEEP HIM ASLEEP.
REGER...
I WANT SOME ANSWERS.
THIS UNDERGROUND--
IF LANDRU'S
SO POWERFUL,
HOW DO YOU SURVIVE?
I DON'T KNOW, CAPTAIN.
SOME OF US ESCAPED
THE DIRECTIVES.
NOT MANY, BUT A FEW.
IT WAS THAT WAY
WHEN THE FIRST ARCHONS CAME.
THE ARCHONS...
TELL ME ABOUT THEM.
THEY HAD INVADED THE BODY,
BUT THEY RESISTED
THE WILL OF LANDRU.
YOU SEE, LANDRU
HAD PULLED THEM DOWN
FROM THE SKIES.
PULLED THEM DOWN
FROM THE SKIES?
A STARSHIP?
MR. SPOCK, THOSE
POWER READINGS YOU
TOOK, ARE THEY...
POWERFUL ENOUGH TO DESTROY
A STARSHIP? AFFIRMATIVE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE,
COME IN.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
THERE ARE HEAT BEAMS
OF SOME KIND
COMING UP
FROM THE PLANET'S
SURFACE.
STATUS REPORT.
OUR SHIELDS
ARE HOLDING,
BUT THEY'RE TAKING
ALL OUR POWER.
IF WE TRY TO WARP
OUT OR EVEN MOVE
ON IMPULSE ENGINES,
WE'LL LOSE
OUR SHIELDS,
AND WE'LL BURN UP
LIKE A CINDER.
ORBIT CONDITION.
CHECKING.
WE'RE GOING DOWN,
CAPTAIN.
UNLESS WE CAN GET
THOSE BEAMS OFF US
SO WE CAN USE
OUR ENGINES,
WE'RE DUE TO HIT
ATMOSPHERE IN LESS
THAN 12 HOURS.
KEEP YOUR SHIELD UP.
DO EVERYTHING YOU CAN
TO MAINTAIN ORBIT.
WE'LL TRY AND LOCATE
THE SOURCE OF THE BEAM
AND STOP IT HERE.
IMPOSSIBLE TO BREAK
AWAY. I'VE TRIED
THE EMERGENCY
BYPASS CIRCUITS,
BUT THEY HAVEN'T
BEEN EFFECTIVE.
[STATIC]
[SPOCK]
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
SENSOR BEAMS,
VERY STRONG.
WE'RE BEING PROBED
IN THIS DIRECTION.
LANDRU.
BLOCK THEM OUT.
TOO STRONG, CAPTAIN.
CAN'T BE BLOCKED.
[WHIRRING SOUNDS]
OOH...
I AM LANDRU.
PROJECTION, CAPTAIN.
UNREAL.
BUT BEAUTIFUL, MR. SPOCK,
WITH NO APPARATUS AT THIS END.
YOU HAVE COME
AS DESTROYERS.
YOU BRING AN INFECTION.
YOU ARE HOLDING MY SHIP.
I DEMAND
THAT YOU RELEASE IT.
YOU HAVE COME TO A WORLD
WITHOUT HATE,
WITHOUT FEAR,
WITHOUT CONFLICT...
NO WAR...
NO DISEASE...
NO CRIME...
NONE OF THE ANCIENT EVILS.
LANDRU
SEEKS TRANQUILITY...
PEACE FOR ALL...
THE UNIVERSAL GOOD.
WE MEAN YOU NO HARM.
OURS IS A MISSION
OF PEACE AND GOOD WILL.
THE GOOD MUST TRANSCEND
THE EVIL.
IT SHALL BE DONE.
SO IT HAS BEEN
SINCE THE BEGINNING.
HE DOESN'T HEAR YOU,
CAPTAIN.
MAYBE HE'LL HEAR THIS.
PUT THAT AWAY.
LANDRU...
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU WILL BE ABSORBED.
YOUR INDIVIDUALITY
WILL MERGE
INTO THE UNITY OF GOOD,
AND IN YOUR SUBMERGENCE
INTO THE COMMON BEING
OF THE BODY,
YOU WILL FIND CONTENTMENT
AND FULFILLMENT.
YOU WILL EXPERIENCE...
THE ABSOLUTE GOOD.
OHH...
[HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING]
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3157.4--
THE ENTERPRISE,
STILL UNDER ATTACK
BY SOME SORT OF HEAT RAYS
FROM THE SURFACE
OF BETA 3,
IS NOW BEING COMMANDED BY
ENGINEERING OFFICER SCOTT.
THE SHORE PARTY
HAS BEEN TAKEN
BY THE CREATURE
CALLED LANDRU.
MR. SPOCK.
WAKE UP.
MR. LESLIE.
WHERE'S DR. McCOY?
HE WAS GONE
WHEN I WOKE UP,
ALONG WITH
THE OTHER GUARD
AND MR. O'NEIL.
I SHOULD SAY
THEY'VE BEEN HERE
AND BEEN REMOVED.
BUT WHERE IS "HERE"?
EVIDENTLY
A MAXIMUM-SECURITY
ESTABLISHMENT.
ARE YOU ARMED?
ALL OUR PHASERS
ARE GONE.
I CHECKED.
THAT'S LOCKED.
OHH.
OH, DOES
MY HEAD ACHE.
THE NATURAL RESULT
OF BEING SUBJECTED
TO A HYPERSONIC.
OH. IS THAT
WHAT IT WAS?
SOUND WAVES.
STRONGER, THEY
MIGHT HAVE KILLED.
AS IT WAS, THEY MERELY
RENDERED US UNCONSCIOUS.
ENOUGH ANALYSIS.
LET'S THINK OF A WAY
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
WHAT ABOUT
THE LAWGIVERS' INABILITY
TO COPE WITH
THE UNEXPECTED?
YOU SHOULDN'T DEPEND
ON THAT HAPPENING
AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
IN A SOCIETY
AS WELL ORGANIZED
AS THIS ONE
SEEMS TO BE,
I CANNOT CONCEIVE
OF SUCH AN OVERSIGHT
GOING UNCORRECTED.
INTERESTING, HOWEVER--
THEIR REACTION
TO YOUR DEFIANCE
WAS REMARKABLY SIMILAR
TO THE REACTION
OF A COMPUTER
WHEN FED INSUFFICIENT
OR CONTRADICTORY DATA.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT THE LAWGIVERS
ARE MERE COMPUTERS,
THAT...
THEY AREN'T HUMAN?
QUITE HUMAN,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S SIMPLY
THAT ALL THE FACTS
ARE NOT YET IN.
THERE ARE GAPS.
[DOOR OPENS]
DOC. HOW--
HELLO, FRIEND.
WE WERE TOLD
TO WAIT HERE.
DOC.
CAN I HELP YOU,
FRIEND?
DON'T YOU KNOW ME?
WE ALL KNOW
ONE ANOTHER
IN LANDRU.
LIKE SULU.
THINK, MAN.
THE ENTERPRISE.
THE SHIP.
REMEMBER?
YOU SPEAK VERY
STRANGELY, FRIEND.
ARE YOU FROM AWAY?
YOU DO REMEMBER!
ASK LANDRU.
HE REMEMBERS.
HE KNOWS,
AND HE WATCHES.
YOU ARE STRANGE.
ARE YOU NOT
OF THE BODY?
COME.
NO.
THEN YOU WILL DIE.
IT'S BEEN
CORRECTED, CAPTAIN.
YOU'D BETTER GO.
ALL RIGHT.
WORK ON BONES.
SEE IF YOU CAN'T--
COME.
DR. McCOY,
WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO HIM?
HE GOES TO JOY,
PEACE,
AND TRANQUILITY.
HE GOES
TO MEET LANDRU.
HAPPINESS
IS TO ALL OF US
BLESSED BY LANDRU.
I AM MARPLON.
IT IS YOUR HOUR.
HAPPY COMMUNING.
WITH THANKS.
WELL?
IMPOSSIBLE.
HE'S UNDER EXTREMELY
POWERFUL CONTROL.
ARE WE JUST
GOING TO STAND HERE?
LITTLE ELSE
WE CAN DO...
UNLESS YOU CAN
THINK OF A WAY
TO GET THROUGH
THAT DOOR.
WELL, THIS IS
SIMPLY RIDICULOUS--
A BUNCH OF
STONE-AGE CHARACTERS
RUNNING AROUND
IN ROBES.
AND APPARENTLY
COMMANDING POWERS
FAR BEYOND
OUR COMPREHENSION.
NOT SIMPLE.
NOT RIDICULOUS.
VERY, VERY DANGEROUS.
YOU...
COME.
JOY TO YOU, FRIEND.
PEACE AND CONTENTMENT
WILL FILL YOU.
YOU WILL KNOW
THE PEACE OF LANDRU.
HAVE NO FEAR, FRIEND.
THE EFFECT IS HARMLESS.
MY NAME IS MARPLON.
I WAS TOO LATE TO SAVE
YOUR FIRST TWO FRIENDS.
THEY HAVE BEEN ABSORBED.
BEWARE OF THEM.
WHAT ABOUT THE CAPTAIN?
HE IS UNHARMED,
UNCHANGED.
I AM THE THIRD MAN
IN REGER'S TRIAD.
WE HAVE BEEN AWAITING
YOUR RETURN.
WE ARE NOT ARCHONS,
MARPLON.
WHATEVER YOU MAY
CALL YOURSELVES,
YOU ARE IN FULFILLMENT
OF PROPHECY.
WE ASK YOUR HELP.
WHERE IS REGER?
HE WILL JOIN US.
HE IS IMMUNE
TO ABSORPTION.
HURRY.
WE HAVE NOT
MUCH TIME.
WHO IS LANDRU?
I CANNOT ANSWER
YOUR QUESTIONS NOW.
LANDRU, HE WILL HEAR.
HERE ARE YOUR WEAPONS.
YOU MAY NEED THEM.
BEHAVE AS YOU SAW
YOUR CAPTAIN BEHAVE.
IT IS DONE.
JOY BE WITH YOU.
PEACE AND
CONTENTMENT.
CAPTAIN--
PEACE AND TRANQUILITY
TO YOU.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
QUITE ALL RIGHT.
BE CAREFUL
OF DR. McCOY.
I UNDERSTAND.
LANDRU.
I AM FORMULATING
A THEORY, CAPTAIN.
AND?
NOT HERE.
THE DOCTOR.
YOU SPEAK IN
STRANGE WHISPERS.
THIS IS NOT THE WAY
OF LANDRU.
JOY BE YOURS,
AND TRANQUILITY,
MY FRIEND.
AND PEACE
AND HARMONY.
ARE YOU
OF THE BODY?
THE BODY IS ONE.
BLESSED
BE THE BODY
AND HEALTH TO ALL
OF ITS PARTS.
MY FRIENDS...
WHAT IS YOUR THEORY,
MR. SPOCK?
THIS IS A SOULLESS
SOCIETY, CAPTAIN.
IT HAS NO SPIRIT,
NO SPARK.
ALL IS INDEED PEACE
AND TRANQUILITY--
THE PEACE OF THE FACTORY,
THE TRANQUILITY
OF THE MACHINE,
ALL PARTS
WORKING IN UNISON.
AND WHEN SOMETHING
UNEXPLAINED HAPPENS...
THEIR ROUTINE
IS DISRUPTED?
UNTIL NEW ORDERS
ARE RECEIVED.
THE QUESTION IS,
WHO GIVES
THOSE ORDERS?
LANDRU.
THERE IS NO LANDRU,
CAPTAIN,
NOT IN
THE HUMAN SENSE.
YOU'RE THINKING
THE SAME THING I AM.
MR. SPOCK,
THE PLUG MUST BE PULLED.
SIR?
LANDRU MUST DIE.
CAPTAIN,
OUR PRIME DIRECTIVE
OF NONINTERFERENCE.
THAT REFERS TO
A LIVING, GROWING CULTURE.
DO YOU THINK THIS ONE IS?
JOY TO YOU ALL,
FRIENDS.
IT IS THE GIFT
OF LANDRU.
I BROUGHT YOUR
SIGNALING DEVICES.
YOU MAY NEED THEM.
WHAT WE REALLY NEED
IS MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT LANDRU.
YOU SAID YOU WANTED US
TO HELP YOU.
PROPHECY SAYS--
NEVER MIND WHAT
THE PROPHECY SAYS.
IF YOU WANT
TO BE LIBERATED
FROM LANDRU,
WE'LL NEED
YOUR HELP.
CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE NOT OF THE BODY!
PEACE...
YOU'RE NOT!
TO YOU, FRIEND.
LAWGIVERS!
PEACE.
TRAITOR! TRAITORS!
TRAITORS!
DOC, I DON'T WANT
TO HURT YOU.
TRAITORS!
AW, DOC...
SPOCK.
ISN'T THAT
SOMEWHAT OLD-FASHIONED?
THE ROBES.
WHERE IS LANDRU?
NO. NO.
WHERE DO WE FIND HIM?
WE DO NOT SEE HIM.
WE HEAR HIM
IN THE HALL
OF AUDIENCES.
IN THIS BUILDING?
YES.
YOU'RE GOING TO
TAKE US THERE.
OH.
SPOCK, CALL THE ENTERPRISE.
OH!
SNAP OUT OF IT!
START ACTING LIKE MEN.
SPOCK TO ENTERPRISE.
STATUS REPORT.
MR. SPOCK, I'VE BEEN
TRYING TO REACH YOU.
REPORT, SCOTT.
THE ORBIT'S
STILL DECAYING.
GIVE IT SIX HOURS,
MORE OR LESS.
THOSE HEAT BEAMS
ARE STILL ON US.
YOU'VE GOT TO CUT
THEM OFF, MR. SPOCK,
OR WE'LL COOK,
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
SCOTTY,
STAND BY.
WE'RE DOING
THE BEST WE CAN.
HOW'S MR. SULU?
HE'S PEACEFUL ENOUGH,
BUT HE WORRIES ME.
PUT A GUARD ON HIM.
ON SULU?
THAT'S AN ORDER.
WATCH HIM.
CAPTAIN OUT.
CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
ABOUT LANDRU.
WELL...THERE WAS WAR,
CONVULSIONS.
THE WORLD WAS
DESTROYING ITSELF.
LANDRU WAS OUR LEADER.
HE SAW THE TRUTH.
HE CHANGED THE WORLD.
HE TOOK US BACK,
BACK TO A SIMPLE TIME,
A TIME OF PEACE
AND TRANQUILITY.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIM?
HE'S STILL ALIVE.
HE IS HERE NOW.
HE SEES. HE HEARS.
WE HAVE DESTROYED
OURSELVES.
PLEASE...
NO MORE.
YOU SAID
YOU WANTED FREEDOM.
IT'S TIME YOU LEARNED THAT
FREEDOM IS NEVER A GIFT.
IT HAS TO BE EARNED.
COME ON.
WE'RE GOING TO
FIND LANDRU.
NO! NO!
I WAS WRONG!
I SUBMIT!
I BEAR MYSELF
TO THE WILL OF LANDRU!
IT'S TOO LATE FOR THAT.
NO! NO! GIVE US HELP!
HELP ME!
ALL RIGHT,
IT'S UP TO YOU.
TAKE US TO LANDRU.
THIS IS THE HALL
OF AUDIENCES.
OPEN IT.
BUT THIS IS LANDRU.
LANDRU SPEAKS HERE.
LANDRU!
WE ARE THE ARCHONS!
WE'VE COME TO SPEAK!
WE ARE
THE ARCHONS.
WE WANT TO
TALK TO YOU.
LANDRU!
HE COMES!
DESPITE MY EFFORTS
TO SAVE YOU,
YOU HAVE INVADED
THE BODY,
AND YOU ARE
CAUSING GREAT HARM.
WE HAVE NO INTENTION
OF CAUSING HARM.
OBLITERATION
IS NECESSARY.
THE INFECTION IS STRONG.
FOR THE GOOD
OF THE BODY,
YOU MUST DIE.
IT IS...
A GREAT SORROW.
WE DO NOT INTEND TO DIE.
ALL WHO SAW YOU,
ALL WHO KNOW
OF YOUR PRESENCE HERE
MUST BE EXCISED.
THE MEMORY OF THE BODY
WILL BE CLEANSED.
LISTEN TO ME.
USELESS, CAPTAIN.
A PROJECTION.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK
AT THE PROJECTOR.
OF COURSE.
IT HAD TO BE.
LANDRU.
A MACHINE.
THIS WHOLE SOCIETY
IS A MACHINE'S CONCEPT
OF PERFECTION--
PEACE, HARMONY...
BUT NO SOUL.
I AM LANDRU.
YOU HAVE INTRUDED.
PULL OUT ITS PLUG,
MR. SPOCK.
YOUR DEVICES
HAVE BEEN NEUTRALIZED.
SO IT SHALL BE WITH YOU.
I AM LANDRU.
LANDRU DIED
6,000 YEARS AGO.
I AM LANDRU.
I AM HE.
ALL THAT HE WAS
I AM--
HIS EXPERIENCE,
HIS KNOWLEDGE.
BUT NOT
HIS WISDOM.
HE MAY HAVE
PROGRAMMED YOU,
BUT HE COULD NOT
HAVE GIVEN YOU
A SOUL.
YOU ARE
A MACHINE.
YOUR STATEMENT
IS IRRELEVANT.
YOU WILL...
BE...
OBLITERATED.
THE GOOD OF THE BODY
IS THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
THE GOOD OF THE BODY, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S THE KEY.
YES.
WHAT IS THE GOOD?
I AM LANDRU.
LANDRU IS DEAD.
YOU ARE A MACHINE.
A QUESTION HAS
BEEN PUT TO YOU.
ANSWER IT.
THE GOOD IS
THE HARMONIOUS CONTINUATION
OF THE BODY.
THE GOOD IS
PEACE, TRANQUILITY.
THE GOOD OF THE BODY
IS THE DIRECTIVE.
THEN I PUT IT TO YOU
THAT YOU HAVE DISOBEYED
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
YOU ARE HARMFUL
TO THE BODY.
THE BODY IS.
IT EXISTS.
IT IS HEALTHY.
THE BODY IS DYING.
YOU...
ARE DESTROYING IT.
DO YOU ASK A QUESTION?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
TO DO JUSTICE TO
THE FULL POTENTIAL
OF EVERY INDIVIDUAL
OF THE BODY?
INSUFFICIENT DATA.
WITHOUT
FREEDOM OF CHOICE,
THERE IS
NO CREATIVITY.
WITHOUT CREATIVITY,
THERE IS NO LIFE.
THE BODY DIES.
THE FAULT IS YOURS.
ARE YOU AIDING
THE BODY,
OR ARE YOU
DESTROYING IT?
I AM NOT PROGRAMMED
TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
LANDRU!
GUIDE US!
NOT NECESSARY,
CAPTAIN.
THEY HAVE
NO GUIDANCE,
POSSIBLY FOR
THE FIRST TIME
IN THEIR LIVES.
LANDRU...
ANSWER THE QUESTION.
PEACE, ORDER,
AND TRANQUILITY
ARE MAINTAINED.
THE BODY LIVES,
BUT I RESERVE
CREATIVITY TO ME.
THEN THE BODY DIES.
CREATIVITY IS NECESSARY
FOR THE HEALTH OF THE BODY.
THIS...
IS...
IMPOSSIBLE!
IS THIS
TRULY LANDRU?
WHAT'S LEFT OF HIM
AFTER HE BUILT
AND PROGRAMMED
THIS MACHINE
6,000 YEARS AGO.
YOU MUST CREATE
THE GOOD.
THAT IS THE WILL
OF LANDRU,
NOTHING ELSE.
BUT THERE IS EVIL.
THEN THE EVIL
MUST BE DESTROYED.
THAT IS
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE,
AND YOU
ARE THE EVIL.
I THINK.
I LIVE.
YOU ARE THE EVIL.
THE EVIL
MUST BE DESTROYED.
FULFILL
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
YOU...
LANDRU, HELP ME!
ARE THE EVIL.
FULFILL
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
HELP ME! HELP ME!
WELL, MARPLON,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN NOW.
I HOPE
YOU'RE UP TO IT.
YOU CAN GET RID
OF THOSE ROBES.
AND IF I WERE YOU,
I'D START LOOKING
FOR ANOTHER JOB.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT ABOUT THE SHIP?
THE HEAT RAYS HAVE GONE,
CAPTAIN,
AND MR. SULU'S
BACK TO NORMAL.
RELIEVING YOU.
EXCELLENT, SCOTTY.
STAND BY TO BEAM UP
LANDING PARTY.
LET'S GO SEE HOW THE
OTHERS ARE DOING.
MARPLON
CAN FINISH UP HERE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3158.7--
THE ENTERPRISE IS
PREPARING TO LEAVE BETA 3
IN STARSYSTEM C-111.
SOCIOLOGIST LINDSTROM
IS REMAINING BEHIND
WITH A PARTY OF EXPERTS
WHO WILL HELP RESTORE
THE PLANET'S CULTURE
TO A HUMAN FORM.
MARVELOUS.
WHAT?
THE LATE LANDRU,
CAPTAIN,
A MARVELOUS FEAT
OF ENGINEERING--
A COMPUTER CAPABLE
OF DIRECTING THE LIVES
OF MILLIONS
OF HUMAN BEINGS.
BUT ONLY A MACHINE,
MR. SPOCK.
THE ORIGINAL LANDRU
PROGRAMMED IT WITH
ALL HIS KNOWLEDGE,
BUT HE COULDN'T
GIVE IT HIS WISDOM,
HIS COMPASSION,
HIS UNDERSTANDING,
HIS SOUL, MR. SPOCK.
PREDICTABLY
METAPHYSICAL.
I PREFER THE CONCRETE,
THE GRASPABLE,
THE PROVABLE.
YOU WOULD MAKE
A SPLENDID COMPUTER,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS VERY KIND
OF YOU, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN...
MR. LINDSTROM
FROM THE SURFACE.
YES, LINDSTROM.
JUST WANTED
TO SAY GOODBYE, CAPTAIN.
HOW'S IT GOING?
COULDN'T BE BETTER.
ALREADY THIS MORNING, WE'VE HAD
HALF A DOZEN DOMESTIC QUARRELS
AND TWO GENUINE
KNOCK-DOWN DRAG-OUTS.
IT MAY NOT BE PARADISE,
BUT IT'S CERTAINLY HUMAN.
SOUNDS MOST PROMISING.
GOOD LUCK.
HOW OFTEN MANKIND
HAS WISHED FOR A WORLD
AS PEACEFUL AND SECURE
AS THE ONE
LANDRU PROVIDED.
YES.
AND WE NEVER GOT IT.
JUST LUCKY, I GUESS.