COMING UP
ON IT FAST, SIR.
ARE YOU CERTAIN
OF YOUR SENSOR READINGS?
DEFINITELY A SPACE
VESSEL OF SOME TYPE.
ORIGIN?
UNKNOWN. IT COULD HARDLY
BE AN EARTH SHIP.
THERE HAVE BEEN NO FLIGHTS
INTO THIS SECTOR FOR YEARS.
I'M PICKING UP
A SIGNAL, SIR.
CAPTAIN, THAT'S THE OLD
MORSE CODE CALL SIGNAL.
THANK YOU.
C-Q...C-Q...
WE'RE READING IT,
LIEUTENANT.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
IT COULDN'T POSSIBLY
BE AN EARTH VESSEL.
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY IT ALWAYS
GIVES YOU PLEASURE
TO SEE ME PROVEN WRONG.
AN EMOTIONAL EARTH
WEAKNESS OF MINE.
THERE IT IS.
AN OLD EARTH VESSEL,
SIMILAR TO
THE DY500 CLASS.
MUCH OLDER--
DY100 CLASS, TO BE EXACT.
CAPTAIN...
THE LAST SUCH VESSEL
WAS BUILT CENTURIES AGO,
BACK IN THE 1990s.
THEN IT'S A DERELICT,
ITS SIGNAL LEFT
ON AUTOMATIC.
OR AN OLD EARTH SHIP
BEING USED BY ALIENS.
WEAPONS STATUS.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
ON MAXIMUM,
PHASERS MANNED, SIR.
BIO-SCANNERS REPORT.
[McCOY]
LIFE SCIENCE BIO-SCANNERS
ARE PICKING UP HEARTBEATS
FROM OVER THERE.
CAN'T BE HUMAN, THOUGH.
THEY'RE TOO FAINT
AND AVERAGE
ONLY FOUR BEATS
PER MINUTE.
SENSOR READING, CAPTAIN.
SOME SORT OF EQUIPMENT
FUNCTIONING
ON THAT VESSEL.
ALL DECKS GO
TO FULL ALERT.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 3141.9--
A FULL HOUR HAS ELAPSED
SINCE INTERCEPTION
OF THE STRANGE VESSEL.
OUR PRESENCE ALONGSIDE
IS STILL BEING
COMPLETELY IGNORED.
ALTHOUGH OUR SENSORS
CONTINUE TO SHOW SIGNS
OF EQUIPMENT
AND LIFE ABOARD,
THERE HAS BEEN NO
INDICATION OF DANGER TO US.
WEAPONS DEPARTMENT--
MAINTAIN BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL OTHER DECKS--
STAND-BY ALERT.
ALL DECKS
ACKNOWLEDGING, SIR.
CONTINUING
TO PICK UP
SOME FORM
OF HEART ACTION
OVER THERE--
VERY FAINT,
VERY SLOW.
SEEMS
TO BE COMING
FROM ABOUT
60 OR 70 BODIES
NEAR AS I CAN
MAKE OUT.
ALIEN BODIES?
COULD BE.
THERE'S NO SIGN
OF BREATHING
OR OTHER FORMS
OF RESPIRATION.
HULL SURFACE IS PITTED
WITH METEOR SCARS.
HOWEVER, SCANNERS
MAKE OUT A NAME--
S.S. BOTANY BAY.
THEN YOU CAN CHECK
THE REGISTRY.
NO SUCH VESSEL LISTED.
RECORDS OF THAT PERIOD
ARE FRAGMENTARY, HOWEVER.
THE MID-1990s WAS THE ERA
OF YOUR LAST SO-CALLED
WORLD WAR.
THE EUGENICS WARS.
OF COURSE--YOUR ATTEMPT
TO IMPROVE THE RACE
THROUGH SELECTIVE BREEDING.
OH,
NOW WAIT A MINUTE.
NOT OUR ATTEMPT,
MR. SPOCK--
A GROUP OF AMBITIOUS
SCIENTISTS'.
I'M SURE
YOU KNOW THE TYPE--
DEVOTED TO LOGIC,
COMPLETELY
UNEMOTIONAL--
DOCTOR, I WOULD
BE PLEASED--
ALL RIGHT, GENTLEMEN,
AS YOU WERE.
RIG FOR TRACTOR BEAM, HELM.
LOCK ONTO THAT VESSEL.
RIGGING FOR
TRACTOR BEAM,
SIR.
THE BRIDGE IS YOURS,
MR. SPOCK.
CARE TO JOIN
THE LANDING PARTY?
WELL, IF YOU'RE
ACTUALLY GIVING
ME A CHOICE--
I'M NOT.
OH, I'LL NEED
SOMEBODY FAMILIAR
WITH THE LATE
20th CENTURY EARTH.
HERE'S A CHANCE
FOR THAT HISTORIAN
TO DO SOMETHING
FOR A CHANGE.
WHAT'S HER NAME...
UH, McIVERS?
LIEUTENANT McGIVERS.
ATTENTION--
THE FOLLOWING PERSONNEL
REPORT
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM--
ENGINEERING OFFICER SCOTT,
LIEUTENANT McGIVERS.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
McGIVERS. ON MY WAY.
WELL, IT LOOKS
LIKE THAT SHIP
IS EXPECTING US.
WE READ
HEAT COMING ON,
COMPLETE
OXYGEN ATMOSPHERE.
VERY INTERESTING.
YOU READY, BONES?
NO.
I SIGNED ABOARD THIS SHIP
TO PRACTICE MEDICINE,
NOT TO HAVE MY ATOMS
SCATTERED BACK AND
FORTH ACROSS SPACE
BY THIS GADGET.
YOU'RE AN OLD-FASHIONED
BOY, McCOY.
WHERE'S THAT HISTORIAN?
COME ON,
LIEUTENANT, UH...
McGIVERS, SIR.
ENERGIZE.
SCOTTY?
DEFINITELY EARTH-TYPE
MECHANISMS, SIR.
20th CENTURY VESSEL--
OLD-TYPE ATOMIC POWER,
BULKY, SOLID...
I THINK THEY USED
TO CALL THEM
TRANSISTOR UNITS.
I'D LOVE TO TEAR
THIS BABY APART.
CAPTAIN,
IT'S A SLEEPER SHIP.
SUSPENDED ANIMATION.
UH-HUH. I'VE SEEN OLD
PHOTOGRAPHS OF THIS.
NECESSARY BECAUSE
OF THE TIME INVOLVED
IN SPACE TRAVEL
UNTIL ABOUT
THE YEAR 2018.
IT TOOK YEARS
JUST TO TRAVEL
FROM ONE PLANET
TO ANOTHER.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THEY'RE STILL ALIVE...
AFTER CENTURIES
OF TRAVEL?
IT'S THEORETICALLY
POSSIBLE.
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF IT BEING TESTED
FOR THIS LONG A PERIOD.
WHAT A HANDSOME
GROUP OF PEOPLE.
JIM, I HAVE
A NEW READING.
THE LIGHTS MUST
HAVE TRIGGERED
SOME MECHANISM.
CAPTAIN, LOOK HERE.
SCOTTY?
BEATS ME
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
WE'VE TRIGGERED SOMETHING,
ALL RIGHT.
THE HEARTBEAT'S
INCREASING--
NOW PASSING EIGHT BEATS
PER MINUTE--
AND THERE ARE SOME SIGNS
OF RESPIRATION BEGINNING.
THIS ONE WAS
PROBABLY PROGRAMMED
TO BE TRIGGERED
FIRST.
COULD HE BE
THE LEADER?
THE LEADER.
LIEUTENANT?
YES, SIR.
THE LEADER WAS OFTEN
SET TO REVIVE FIRST.
THIS WOULD
ALLOW HIM TO DECIDE
WHETHER THE CONDITIONS
WARRANTED REVIVAL
OF THE OTHERS.
HEARTBEAT NOW APPROACHING
40 PER MINUTE.
THE RESPIRATION PATTERN
IS FIRMING UP.
FROM THE NORTHERN
INDIA AREA, I'D GUESS.
PROBABLY A SIKH.
THEY WERE THE MOST
FANTASTIC WARRIORS.
HEARTBEAT NOW 52
AND INCREASING.
THE OTHERS?
NO CHANGE, AND THEY'RE
MIXED TYPES--
WESTERN, MID-EUROPEAN,
LATIN, ORIENTAL.
A MAN FROM
THE 20th CENTURY
COMING ALIVE.
MAYBE.
HEARTBEAT DROPPING.
CIRCUIT SHORTING.
PROBABLY
SOME DUST.
HEARTBEAT NOW 30,
DROPPING FAST.
THERE'S
A HEART FLUTTER.
HE'S DYING.
DO SOMETHING,
CAPTAIN.
CAN WE?
TAKE AN HOUR
TO FIGURE OUT.
WHAT HAPPENS IF
WE GET HIM OUT
OF THERE?
HE'LL DIE IN SECONDS
IF WE DON'T.
How...long?
HOW LONG...HAVE YOU
BEEN SLEEPING?
TWO CENTURIES
WE ESTIMATE.
LANDING PARTY
TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
GO AHEAD,
BOARDING PARTY.
WE READ YOU.
LOCK IN ON DR. McCOY'S BEAM.
HE'S TRANSPORTING BACK
WITH A CASUALTY
WE DISCOVERED HERE.
MAGNIFICENT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL--
ALONGSIDE THE S.S. BOTANY BAY
FOR 10 HOURS NOW.
A BOARDING PARTY
OF ENGINEERING
AND MEDICAL SPECIALISTS
ARE NOW COMPLETING
THEIR EXAMINATION
OF THE MYSTERIOUS VESSEL.
ATTEMPTS TO REVIVE
OTHER SLEEPERS
AWAIT OUR
SUCCESS OR FAILURE
WITH THE CASUALTY
ALREADY BEAMED OVER.
DR. McCOY
IS FRANKLY AMAZED
AT HIS PHYSICAL
AND RECUPERATIVE POWER.
KIRK TO BOARDING PARTY.
SCOTT HERE.
SCOTTY, ANY RECORDS,
LOG BOOKS OF ANY KIND?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
IT APPEARS THEY WERE
IN SUSPENDED ANIMATION
WHEN THE SHIP TOOK OFF.
HOW MANY ALIVE?
12 UNITS
HAVE MALFUNCTIONED,
LEAVING 72
STILL OPERATING.
30 OF THOSE ARE WOMEN.
KIRK OUT.
72 ALIVE...
A GROUP OF PEOPLE DATING
BACK TO THE 1990s.
A DISCOVERY OF SOME
IMPORTANCE, MR. SPOCK.
THERE ARE A GREAT MANY
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS
ABOUT THOSE YEARS.
A STRANGE, VIOLENT PERIOD
IN YOUR HISTORY.
I FIND NO RECORD
WHATSOEVER OF AN
S.S. BOTANY BAY.
CAPTAIN,
THE DY100 CLASS VESSEL
WAS DESIGNED
FOR INTERPLANETARY
TRAVEL ONLY.
WITH SIMPLE
NUCLEAR-POWERED ENGINES,
STAR TRAVEL WAS CONSIDERED
IMPRACTICAL AT THAT TIME.
IT WAS 10,000-T0-1
AGAINST THEIR MAKING IT
TO ANOTHER STAR SYSTEM.
AND WHY
NO RECORD OF THE TRIP?
BOTANY BAY...
THAT WAS THE NAME
OF A PENAL COLONY
ON THE SHORES
OF AUSTRALIA,
WASN'T IT?
IF THEY TOOK
THAT NAME
FOR THEIR VESSEL...
IF YOU'RE SUGGESTING
THIS WAS A PENAL
DEPORTATION VESSEL,
YOU'VE ARRIVED AT A TOTALLY
ILLOGICAL CONCLUSION.
OH?
YOUR EARTH WAS ON THE VERGE
OF A DARK AGES.
WHOLE POPULATIONS WERE BEING
BOMBED OUT OF EXISTENCE.
A GROUP OF CRIMINALS
COULD HAVE BEEN DEALT
WITH FAR MORE EFFICIENTLY
THAN WASTING ONE OF THEIR
MOST ADVANCED SPACESHIPS.
YES.
SO MUCH FOR MY THEORY.
I'M STILL WAITING
TO HEAR YOURS.
EVEN A THEORY REQUIRES
SOME FACTS, CAPTAIN.
SO FAR...
I HAVE NONE.
AND THAT IRRITATES YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
IRRITATION?
YEAH.
I AM NOT CAPABLE
OF THAT EMOTION.
MY APOLOGIES, MR. SPOCK.
YOU SUSPECT SOME
DANGER IN THEM?
INSUFFICIENT FACTS ALWAYS
INVITE DANGER, CAPTAIN.
WELL, I'D BETTER
GET SOME FACTS.
RIG FOR TOWING.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
MAKE COURSE
FOR STARBASE 12.
AYE, SIR.
THAT WILL BE ALL.
BONES?
HE'LL LIVE.
MY COMPLIMENTS.
NO, I'M GOOD,
BUT NOT THAT GOOD.
THERE'S SOMETHING
INSIDE THIS MAN
THAT REFUSES
TO ACCEPT DEATH.
NOW, LOOK AT THAT--
EVEN AS HE IS NOW,
HIS
HEART VALVE ACTION
HAS TWICE THE POWER
OF YOURS AND MINE,
LUNG EFFICIENCY
50% BETTER.
AN IMPROVED BREED
OF HUMAN.
THAT'S WHAT
THE EUGENICS WAR
WAS ALL ABOUT.
I'D ESTIMATE HE
COULD LIFT US BOTH
WITH ONE ARM.
BE INTERESTING
TO SEE IF HIS BRAIN
MATCHES HIS BODY.
DOCTOR, WILL HE LIVE?
IT APPEARS HE WILL,
LIEUTENANT.
I'D LIKE
TO TALK TO YOU.
IF I WERE TO RATE
YOUR PERFORMANCE
AS A MEMBER OF THE
LANDING PARTY TODAY--
I KNOW, SIR.
I'M SORRY.
LIEUTENANT,
AT ANY ONE TIME,
THE SAFETY
OF THIS ENTIRE VESSEL
MIGHT DEPEND ON
THE PERFORMANCE OF
A SINGLE CREWMAN ABOARD,
AND THE FACT
THAT YOU FIND A MAN
STRANGELY COMPELLING
TO YOU PERSONALLY--
NOT PERSONALLY, CAPTAIN.
PROFESSIONALLY.
MY PROFESSION IS HISTORIAN,
AND TO FIND A SPECIMEN
FROM THE PAST ALIVE--
I MEAN, THE SHEER DELIGHT
OF EXAMINING HIS MIND.
AND MEN WERE MORE
ADVENTURESOME THEN...
BOLDER, MORE COLORFUL?
YES, SIR,
I THINK THEY WERE.
GOOD.
IF I CAN HAVE HONESTY,
IT'S EASIER
TO OVERLOOK MISTAKES.
THAT'S ALL.
YES, SIR.
A PITY YOU WASTED YOUR
LIFE ON COMMAND, JIM.
YOU'D HAVE MADE
A FAIR PSYCHOLOGIST.
FAIR?
SICK BAY TO LAB.
ANYTHING NEW
ON THOSE BIOS?
THEY ALL CAME OUT FINE,
DOCTOR.
GOOD. McCOY OUT.
WELL, EITHER CHOKE ME
OR CUT MY THROAT.
MAKE UP YOUR MIND.
ENGLISH.
I THOUGHT I DREAMED
HEARING IT.
WHERE AM I?
YOU'RE--
YOU'RE IN BED,
HOLDING A KNIFE
AT YOUR DOCTOR'S THROAT.
ANSWER MY QUESTION.
IT WOULD BE MOST EFFECTIVE
IF YOU WOULD CUT
THE CAROTID ARTERY
JUST UNDER THE LEFT EAR.
I LIKE A BRAVE MAN.
I WAS SIMPLY TRYING
TO AVOID AN ARGUMENT.
YOU'RE ABOARD THE UNITED
SPACESHIP ENTERPRISE.
YOUR VESSEL IS IN TOW.
I REMEMBER
A VOICE...
DID I HEAR IT SAY
I HAD BEEN SLEEPING
FOR TWO CENTURIES?
THAT IS CORRECT.
WHERE IS YOUR CAPTAIN?
I HAVE MANY QUESTIONS.
BRIDGE.
I HAVE A PATIENT HERE WITH
MANY QUESTIONS, CAPTAIN.
ON MY WAY.
JAMES KIRK, COMMANDING
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
I SEE.
AND YOUR NAME?
I HAVE A FEW QUESTIONS
FIRST.
WHAT IS YOUR HEADING?
OUR HEADING
IS STARBASE 12,
A PLANET IN THE GAMMA 400
STAR SYSTEM--
OUR COMMAND BASE
IN THIS SECTOR.
IS THAT OF ANY USE TO YOU?
AND, UM...
MY PEOPLE?
72 OF YOUR
LIFE-SUPPORT CANISTERS
ARE STILL FUNCTIONING.
YOU WILL REVIVE THEM.
AS SOON AS WE REACH
STARBASE 12.
I SEE.
AND NOW...
KHAN IS MY NAME.
KHAN--NOTHING ELSE?
KHAN.
WHAT WAS THE EXACT DATE
OF YOUR LIFT-OFF?
WE KNOW IT WAS SOMETIME
IN THE EARLY 1990s.
I FIND MYSELF GROWING
FATIGUED, DOCTOR.
MAY WE CONTINUE THIS...
QUESTIONING
AT SOME OTHER TIME?
THE FACTS I NEED, MR. KHAN,
WILL TAKE VERY LITTLE TIME.
FOR EXAMPLE, THE NATURE
OF YOUR EXPEDITION--
JIM...
A LITTLE LATER
MIGHT BE BETTER.
CAPTAIN,
I WONDER IF I COULD
HAVE SOMETHING TO READ
DURING MY CONVALESCENCE.
I WAS ONCE
AN ENGINEER OF SORTS.
I WOULD BE MOST
INTERESTED IN STUDYING
THE TECHNICAL MANUALS
ON YOUR VESSEL.
YES, I UNDERSTAND.
YOU HAVE 200 YEARS
OF CATCHING UP TO DO.
PRECISELY.
THEY'RE AVAILABLE
TO ANY PATIENT ON
THE VIEWING SCREEN.
DR. McCOY WILL SHOW YOU
HOW TO TIE INTO
THE LIBRARY TAPES.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOU ARE
VERY COOPERATIVE.
THIS KHAN IS NOT
WHAT I EXPECTED
OF A 20th CENTURY
MAN.
I NOTE HE'S MAKING
CONSIDERABLE USE OF
OUR TECHNICAL LIBRARY.
COMMON COURTESY,
MR. SPOCK.
OF HE'S GONNA SPEND
THE REST OF HIS DAYS
IN OUR TIME,
IT'S ONLY DECENT TO
HELP HIM CATCH UP.
WOULD YOU ESTIMATE
HIM TO BE A PRODUCT
OF
SELECTIVE BREEDING?
THERE IS THAT POSSIBILITY,
CAPTAIN.
HIS AGE WOULD BE CORRECT.
IN 1993, A GROUP
OF THESE YOUNG SUPERMEN
DID SEIZE POWER
SIMULTANEOUSLY
IN OVER 40 NATIONS.
WELL, THEY WERE
HARDLY SUPERMEN.
THEY WERE AGGRESSIVE,
ARROGANT.
THEY BEGAN TO BATTLE
AMONG THEMSELVES.
BECAUSE THE SCIENTISTS
OVERLOOKED ONE FACT--
SUPERIOR ABILITY
BREEDS SUPERIOR AMBITION.
INTERESTING, IF TRUE.
THEY CREATED A GROUP OF
ALEXANDERS, NAPOLEONS.
I HAVE COLLECTED
SOME NAMES
AND MADE SOME COUNTS.
BY MY ESTIMATE,
THERE WERE SOME 80 OR 90
OF THESE YOUNG SUPERMEN
UNACCOUNTED FOR
WHEN THEY WERE
FINALLY DEFEATED.
THAT FACT ISN'T
IN THE HISTORY TEXTS.
WOULD YOU REVEAL
TO WAR-WEARY POPULATIONS
THAT SOME 80 NAPOLEONS
MIGHT STILL BE ALIVE?
SHIP'S HISTORIAN,
LIEUTENANT--
MARLA McGIVERS.
YES.
I AM TOLD
YOU PARTICIPATED
IN MY REBIRTH.
IN A SMALL WAY.
I'VE BEEN READING UP
ON STARSHIPS,
BUT THEY HAVE
ONE LUXURY
NOT MENTIONED
IN THE MANUALS.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
MY NAME IS KHAN.
PLEASE SIT
AND ENTERTAIN ME.
I'D LIKE SOME
HISTORICAL INFORMATION
ABOUT YOUR SHIP,
ITS PURPOSE AND--
AND WHY DO YOU
WEAR YOUR HAIR
IN SUCH AN
UNCOMPLIMENTARY FASHION?
IT'S COMFORTABLE.
BUT IT'S NOT ATTRACTIVE.
THERE...
SOFT...
NATURAL...
SIMPLE.
MR. KHAN, I'M HERE
ON BUSINESS.
YOU FIND
NO PLEASURE HERE?
MY INTEREST IS
SCIENTIFIC. MEN OF--
THAT IS, THE WORLD
OF THE PAST--
I'M SURE
YOU UNDERSTAND
TO ACTUALLY TALK
TO A MAN
OF YOUR CENTURY--
THERE...
SIMPLE...
SOFT...
PLEASE REMEMBER.
PERHAPS SOME OTHER TIME,
WHEN YOU FEEL MORE LIKE
TALKING ABOUT THE PAST.
I'M GLAD YOU CAME.
PLEASE DO IT AGAIN.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
ARE WE EXPECTING
A FLEET ADMIRAL
FOR DINNER?
LIEUTENANT McGIVERS' IDEA
TO WELCOME KHAN
TO OUR CENTURY.
JUST HOW STRONGLY
IS SHE ATTRACTED TO HIM?
WELL, THERE AREN'T
ANY REGULATIONS
AGAINST ROMANCE, JIM.
MY CURIOSITY IS OFFICIAL,
NOT PERSONAL, BONES.
WELL,
HE HAS A MAGNETISM,
ALMOST ELECTRIC--
YOU FELT IT--
AND IT COULD
OVERPOWER McGIVERS
WITH HER
PREOCCUPATION
WITH THE PAST.
THANK YOU.
I HOPED, UH,
YOU MIGHT GUIDE ME
TO OUR
DINNER ENGAGEMENT.
VERY GOOD.
FINE TECHNIQUE.
IT'S A GLADIATOR
NAMED FLAVIUS.
HE ONCE---
AND YOU'VE
REARRANGED
YOUR HAIR FOR ME.
EXCELLENT.
ALL BOLD MEN
FROM THE PAST.
RICHARD,
LEIF ERICSON,
NAPOLEON.
A HOBBY OF YOURS,
SUCH MEN?
I AM HONORED.
THANK YOU.
BUT I CAUTION YOU.
SUCH MEN DARE TAKE
WHAT THEY WANT.
FORGIVE MY CURIOSITY,
MR. KHAN,
BUT MY OFFICERS
ARE ANXIOUS
TO KNOW MORE ABOUT YOUR
EXTRAORDINARY JOURNEY.
AND HOW YOU MANAGED
TO KEEP IT OUT OF
THE HISTORY BOOKS.
ADVENTURE, CAPTAIN.
ADVENTURE.
THERE WAS LITTLE ELSE
LEFT ON EARTH.
THERE WAS THE WAR
TO END TYRANNY.
MANY CONSIDERED THAT
A NOBLE EFFORT.
TYRANNY, SIR?
OR AN ATTEMPT
TO UNIFY HUMANITY?
UNIFY, SIR?
LIKE A TEAM OF ANIMALS
UNDER ONE WHIP?
I KNOW SOMETHING
OF THOSE YEARS, REMEMBER.
IT WAS A TIME
OF GREAT DREAMS,
OF GREAT ASPIRATION.
UNDER DOZENS
OF PETTY DICTATORSHIPS.
ONE MAN WOULD
HAVE RULED EVENTUALLY,
AS ROME
UNDER CAESAR.
THINK OF
ITS ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
THEN YOUR SYMPATHIES
WERE WITH--
YOU ARE AN EXCELLENT
TACTICIAN, CAPTAIN.
YOU LET YOUR
SECOND-IN-COMMAND ATTACK
WHILE YOU SIT AND WATCH
FOR WEAKNESS.
YOU HAVE A TENDENCY
TO EXPRESS IDEAS
IN MILITARY TERMS,
MR. KHAN.
THIS IS
A SOCIAL OCCASION.
IT HAS BEEN SAID
THAT SOCIAL OCCASIONS
ARE ONLY WARFARE CONCEALED.
MANY PREFER IT
MORE HONEST,
MORE OPEN.
YOU FLED. WHY,
WERE YOU AFRAID?
I'VE NEVER BEEN AFRAID.
BUT YOU LEFT AT THE
VERY TIME MANKIND
NEEDED COURAGE.
WE OFFERED
THE WORLD ORDER!
WE?
EXCELLENT.
BUT IF YOU
WILL EXCUSE ME,
GENTLEMEN AND LADIES,
I GROW FATIGUED AGAIN.
WITH YOUR
PERMISSION, CAPTAIN,
I WILL RETURN
TO MY QUARTERS.
[DOOR BUZZES]
I WANTED
TO APOLOGIZE.
THEY HAD NO RIGHT
TO TREAT YOU
THAT WAY.
QUITE UNDERSTANDABLE,
SINCE I'M SOMETHING
OF A MYSTERY TO THEM.
YOU'RE
NO MYSTERY TO ME.
I KNOW EXACTLY
WHO YOU ARE.
DO YOU?
MM-HMM.
LEIF ERICSON,
RICHARD
THE LION-HEARTED,
NAPOLEON.
I DON'T KNOW IF
YOU'RE GOING TO LIKE
LIVING IN OUR TIME.
THEN I'LL HAVE
TO REMOLD IT
TO MY LIKING.
PLEASE DON'T.
GO.
OR STAY.
BUT DO IT
BECAUSE IT IS
WHAT YOU WISH TO DO.
WELL?
I'LL STAY
A LITTLE LONGER.
HOW MANY MINUTES
DO YOU GRACIOUSLY OFFER?
I ONLY MEANT--
THIS GROWS TIRESOME.
YOU MUST NOW
ASK TO STAY.
I'D LIKE TO STAY.
PLEASE.
OPEN YOUR HEART.
WILL YOU OPEN
YOUR HEART?
YES.
I INTEND TO TAKE
THIS SHIP.
DO YOU AGREE?
OH, PLEASE
DON'T ASK ME--
I NEED YOUR HELP.
YOU WON'T
HARM ANYONE?
NOW YOU
QUESTION ME?
NO.
WILL YOU
ASSIST ME?
OH, PLEASE, KHAN,
DON'T ASK ME--
LEAVE ME THEN.
GO, I SAY.
NO.
I PROMISE.
I'LL DO ANYTHING
YOU ASK.
NAME--
KHAN.
AS WE
KNOW HIM TODAY.
NAME--
KHAN NOONIEN SINGH.
FROM 1992 THROUGH 1996,
ABSOLUTE RULER OF MORE THAN
A QUARTER OF YOUR WORLD,
FROM ASIA THROUGH
THE MIDDLE EAST.
THE LAST OF THE TYRANTS
TO BE OVERTHROWN.
I MUST CONFESS,
GENTLEMEN.
I'VE ALWAYS HELD A
SNEAKING ADMIRATION
FOR THIS ONE.
HE WAS THE BEST
OF THE TYRANTS
AND THE MOST DANGEROUS.
THEY WERE SUPERMEN
IN A SENSE.
STRONGER, BRAVER,
CERTAINLY MORE
AMBITIOUS, MORE DARING.
GENTLEMEN,
THIS ROMANTICISM
ABOUT A RUTHLESS
DICTATOR IS--
MR. SPOCK, WE HUMANS
HAVE A STREAK
OF BARBARISM IN US.
APPALLING, BUT THERE,
NEVERTHELESS.
THERE WERE
NO MASSACRES
UNDER HIS RULE.
AND AS
LITTLE FREEDOM.
NO WARS UNTIL
HE WAS ATTACKED.
GENTLEMEN.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU MISUNDERSTAND US.
WE CAN BE AGAINST HIM
AND ADMIRE HIM
ALL AT THE SAME TIME.
ILLOGICAL.
TOTALLY.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
PUT A 24-HOUR SECURITY
ON MR. KHAN'S QUARTERS,
EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY.
AHH.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I WAS, UM,
LOST IN THOUGHT.
MY DOOR--
LOCKED FROM OUTSIDE,
A GUARD POSTED.
UNUSUAL TREATMENT
FOR KHAN
NOONIEN SINGH.
EXCELLENT.
YOU IDENTIFIED ME
WITH YOUR COMPUTER
SYSTEM, I IMAGINE.
I'D LIKE
THOSE ANSWERS NOW.
FIRST...
THE PURPOSE OF
YOUR STAR FLIGHT.
A NEW LIFE,
A CHANCE TO BUILD
A WORLD...
OTHER THINGS
I DOUBT YOU
WOULD UNDERSTAND.
WHY?
BECAUSE I'M
NOT A PRODUCT OF
CONTROLLED GENETICS?
CAPTAIN, ALTHOUGH
YOUR ABILITIES
INTRIGUE ME,
YOU ARE QUITE
HONESTLY INFERIOR.
MENTALLY, PHYSICALLY.
IN FACT, I AM SURPRISED
HOW LITTLE IMPROVEMENT
THERE HAS BEEN
IN HUMAN EVOLUTION.
OH, THERE HAS BEEN
TECHNICAL ADVANCEMENT,
BUT, UH,
HOW LITTLE MAN HIMSELF
HAS CHANGED.
YES, IT APPEARS
WE WILL DO WELL
IN YOUR CENTURY,
CAPTAIN.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?
THANK YOU.
THEY'VE ALL
BEEN ANSWERED.
MOVE AWAY.
OTTO.
JOAQUIN.
THE TRIP IS OVER.
THE BATTLE
BEGINS AGAIN.
ONLY THIS TIME IT'S
NOT A WORLD WE WIN.
IT'S A UNIVERSE.
KATI.
ON COURSE, SIR.
WARP FACTOR TWO.
MAINTAIN.
[BEEP BEEP]
BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN,
SECURITY HERE.
KHAN'S ESCAPED.
SOUND
SECURITY ALERT.
SECURITY ALERT,
CAPTAIN.
COMMUNICATION
CHANNELS ARE
JAMMED, CAPTAIN.
TURBO ELEVATORS
INOPERATIVE.
JAMMED, CAPTAIN.
ATMOSPHERIC CONTROLS
CUT OFF.
USELESS.
THEY'RE ON OVERRIDE
IN ENGINEERING.
ENGINEERING.
SCOTTY. THIS
IS THE BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HE'S NOT ABLE
TO ANSWER YOU
AT THE MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
YOUR SHIP IS MINE.
I HAVE SHUT OFF
THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEM
TO YOUR BRIDGE,
JAMMED UP
YOUR EXIT ROUTES.
I AM WILLING
TO NEGOTIATE.
FLOOD ALL DECKS
WITH NEURAL GAS.
IMPOSSIBLE.
INTRUDER CONTROL
SYSTEMS INOPERATIVE.
MR. KHAN
WAS VERY THOROUGH
IN HIS STUDY
OF OUR TECH MANUALS.
CONTACT STARBASE 12.
ALL CHANNELS ARE
TOTALLY JAMMED,
CAPTAIN.
BRILLIANT.
EVERY CONTINGENCY
ANTICIPATED.
YOUR AIR SHOULD BE GETTING
QUITE THIN BY NOW.
DO YOU SURRENDER
THE BRIDGE?
NEGATIVE.
ACADEMIC, CAPTAIN.
REFUSE, AND EVERY PERSON ON
THE BRIDGE WILL SUFFOCATE.
STAR DATE--
3142.8.
THEY HAVE MY SHIP,
DISCARDING THEIR
OWN WORTHLESS VESSEL.
ONLY MOMENTS OF AIR
LEFT ON THE BRIDGE NOW.
COMMENDATIONS RECOMMENDED
FOR LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TECHNICIANS FIRST CLASS
THULE AND HARRISON...
LIEUTENANT SPINELLI...
AND, OF COURSE, MR. SPOCK.
I TAKE
FULL RESPONSIBILITY...
I TAKE FULL--
NOTHING
EVER CHANGES,
EXCEPT MAN.
YOUR TECHNICAL
ACCOMPLISHMENTS?
IMPROVE
A MECHANICAL DEVICE
AND YOU MAY
DOUBLE PRODUCTIVITY.
BUT IMPROVE MAN...
AND YOU GAIN
A THOUSANDFOLD.
I AM SUCH A MAN.
JOIN ME.
I'LL TREAT YOU WELL.
I NEED YOUR TRAINING
TO OPERATE A VESSEL
THIS COMPLEX.
WHERE IS
CAPTAIN KIRK?
I SEE NOW I MADE
ONE SERIOUS ERROR.
YOU ARE
THE COMMUNICATIONS
OFFICER?
ENGAGE THE VIEWING
SCREEN, PLEASE.
NO!
I SHOULD
HAVE REALIZED
THAT SUFFOCATING
TOGETHER
ON THE BRIDGE
WOULD CREATE
HEROIC CAMARADERIE
AMONG YOU.
BUT IT IS QUITE
A DIFFERENT THING
TO SIT BY AND
WATCH IT HAPPENING
TO SOMEONE ELSE.
ENGAGE
THE VIEWING SCREEN.
I'M SURE
YOU RECOGNIZE
YOUR MEDICAL
DECOMPRESSION
CHAMBER HERE,
DOCTOR...
AND THE MEANING
OF THAT INDICATOR.
YOUR CAPTAIN WILL DIE.
IF YOU JOIN ME,
MR. SPOCK,
I WILL SAVE HIS LIFE.
MY VESSEL WAS USELESS.
I NEED YOU AND YOURS
TO SELECT
A COLONY PLANET,
ONE WITH A POPULATION
WILLING TO BE LED
BY US.
TO BE CONQUERED
BY YOU.
A STARSHIP WOULD MAKE
THAT MOST SIMPLE,
WOULDN'T IT?
EACH OF YOU IN TURN
WILL GO IN THERE...
DIE WHILE
THE OTHERS WATCH.
KHAN.
THERE'S NO REASON
I MUST WATCH THIS,
IS THERE?
BUT I HOPED
YOU WOULD BE STRONGER.
IF ANY ONE OF YOU
JOINS ME,
ANY ONE...
I'LL LET HIM LIVE.
IT'S SO USELESS!
[BEEP BEEP]
WE'VE LOST
THE CHANNEL.
HOW DO
I REGAIN PICTURE?
IT DOES NOT MATTER.
THE CAPTAIN IS DEAD.
TAKE MR. SPOCK NEXT.
KHAN SAID TO WATCH HIM
VERY CLOSELY.
HE MAY DECIDE
TO COOPERATE.
CAPTAIN,
I SAVED YOUR LIFE.
NOW PLEASE
DON'T KILL HIM.
SURPRISED TO SEE YOU,
CAPTAIN, THOUGH PLEASED.
I'M A LITTLE
PLEASED MYSELF.
SITUATION?
KHAN IS
HOLDING OUR STAFF
IN THE BRIEFING ROOM.
HIS MEN HAVE CONTROL
OF THE SHIP.
OUR ONLY CHANCE
IS THE INTRUDER
CONTROL CIRCUIT,
ALTHOUGH
HE'S CUT IT OFF
AT THE BRIDGE.
THERE'S
A RELAY JUNCTION
DOWN THE CORRIDOR.
GAS ALL DECKS
BUT THIS ONE.
ARMORY,
THIS IS KHAN.
REPORT.
RODRIGUEZ.
LING.
McPHERSON.
ANYONE, REPORT STATUS.
WHERE'S KHAN?
I DON'T KNOW. HE GOT OUT
JUST AS THE GAS--
[BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
ANESTHESIA GAS
IN ALL SECTIONS
EXCEPT ENGINEERING.
SOMEONE JUST CLOSED
THAT LINE.
CAPTAIN, ACKNOWLEDGE.
UNABLE TO FLOOD
ENGINEERING SECTION.
I SUSPECT...
THIS IS SCOTT.
CAPTAIN'S HEADED
FOR THE ENGINEERING
SECTION.
I'LL FOLLOW
IN CASE--
NEGATIVE. WE MUST
RETAKE THE VESSEL
WHILE
THE ANESTHESIA LASTS.
MEET ME
IN THE ARMORY.
I'M BLOWING IT
CLEAR FIRST.
SPOCK OUT.
[BEEP BEEP]
IF I UNDERSTOOD
YOUR MANUALS,
THAT'S AN OVERLOAD
IN PROGRESS.
YOUR SHIP FLARES UP
LIKE AN EXPLODING SUN
WITHIN MINUTES.
I HAVE FIVE TIMES
YOUR STRENGTH.
YOU'RE NO MATCH
FOR ME.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 3143.3.
CONTROL OF THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN REGAINED.
I WISH MY NEXT DECISIONS
WERE NO MORE DIFFICULT.
KHAN AND HIS PEOPLE--
WHAT A WASTE
TO PUT THEM IN
A REORIENTATION CENTER.
AND WHAT DO I DO
ABOUT McGIVERS?
RECORD TAPES ENGAGED
AND READY, CAPTAIN.
[DING DING]
THIS HEARING
IS NOW IN SESSION.
UNDER THE AUTHORITY
VESTED IN ME
BY STARFLEET
COMMAND...
I DECLARE ALL CHARGES
AND SPECIFICATIONS
IN THIS MATTER
HAVE BEEN DROPPED.
JIM. AGREED YOU HAVE
THE AUTHORITY--
MR. SPOCK, I BELIEVE
OUR HEADING
TAKES US NEAR THE CETI
ALPHA STAR SYSTEM.
QUITE CORRECT,
CAPTAIN.
PLANET NUMBER
FIVE THERE
IS HABITABLE,
ALTHOUGH
A BIT SAVAGE,
SOMEWHAT
INHOSPITABLE.
BUT NO MORE THAN AUSTRALIA'S
BOTANY BAY COLONY WAS
AT THE BEGINNING.
THOSE MEN WENT ON TO TAME
A CONTINENT, MR. KHAN.
CAN YOU TAME A WORLD?
HAVE YOU EVER
READ MILTON, CAPTAIN?
YES.
I UNDERSTAND.
LIEUTENANT
MARLA McGIVERS.
GIVEN A CHOICE
OF COURT-MARTIAL
OR ACCOMPANYING
THEM THERE...
IT WILL BE DIFFICULT.
A STRUGGLE AT FIRST,
EVEN TO STAY ALIVE,
TO FIND FOOD.
I'LL GO
WITH HIM, SIR.
A SUPERIOR WOMAN.
I WILL TAKE HER.
AND I'VE GOTTEN
SOMETHING ELSE
I WANTED--
A WORLD TO WIN,
AN EMPIRE TO BUILD.
THIS HEARING
IS CLOSED.
IT'S A SHAME
FOR A GOOD SCOTSMAN
TO ADMIT IT,
BUT I'M NOT UP
ON MILTON.
THE STATEMENT
LUCIFER MADE
WHEN HE FELL
INTO THE PIT.
"IT IS BETTER
TO RULE IN HELL
THAN SERVE
IN HEAVEN."
HUH.
IT WOULD BE
INTERESTING, CAPTAIN,
TO RETURN TO THAT WORLD
IN A HUNDRED YEARS
AND TO LEARN
WHAT CROP HAS SPRUNG
FROM THE SEED
YOU PLANTED TODAY.
YES, MR. SPOCK,
IT WOULD INDEED.