Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3192.1.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS EN ROUTE
TO STAR CLUSTER
NGC321.
OBJECTIVE--TO OPEN
DIPLOMATIC RELATIONS
WITH THE CIVILIZATIONS
KNOWN TO BE THERE.
WE HAVE SENT A MESSAGE
TO EMINIAR VII,
PRINCIPAL PLANET
OF THE STAR CLUSTER,
INFORMING THEM
OF OUR FRIENDLY INTENTIONS.
WE ARE AWAITING
AN ANSWER.
NOTHING YET,
LIEUTENANT?
NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
HAILING FREQUENCIES
ARE OPEN.
HAVE YOU RECEIVED
AN ANSWER TO YOUR
MESSAGE YET, CAPTAIN?
NOTHING YET,
AMBASSADOR.
WE'RE AWAITING A REPLY.
TODAY IS THE FIRST TIME
WE'VE HAD ANY EVIDENCE
THAT THEY'VE PICKED UP
OUR SIGNAL.
CAPTAIN, MESSAGE COMING IN
FROM EMINIAR VII.
SIR, IT'S CODE 710.
ARE YOU SURE?
POSITIVE.
IT REPEATS OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
IS THAT SUPPOSED
TO MEAN SOMETHING?
CODE 710 MEANS
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
ARE WE TO APPROACH
THAT PLANET--
NO CIRCUMSTANCES
WHATSOEVER.
YOU WILL DISREGARD
THAT SIGNAL, CAPTAIN.
MR. FOX,
IT IS THEIR PLANET.
CAPTAIN,
IN THE PAST 20 YEARS,
THOUSANDS OF LIVES
HAVE BEEN LOST
IN THIS QUADRANT--
LIVES THAT
COULD HAVE BEEN SAVED
IF THE FEDERATION
HAD A TREATY FOR HERE.
WE NEED
TO HAVE THAT PORT,
AND I'M HERE TO GET IT.
BY DISREGARDING
CODE 710,
YOU MIGHT WELL INVOLVE US
IN AN INTERPLANETARY WAR.
I'M QUITE PREPARED
TO TAKE THAT RISK.
YOU ARE.
I'M THINKING ABOUT
THIS SHIP, MY CREW.
I HAVE MY ORDERS, CAPTAIN,
AND NOW YOU HAVE YOURS.
YOU WILL PROCEED
ON COURSE.
ACHIEVE ORBIT STATUS
AND JUST LEAVE
THE REST TO ME.
YOU ARE WELL AWARE
THAT MY MISSION GIVES ME
THE POWER OF COMMAND.
I NOW EXERCISE IT.
YOU WILL PROCEED
ON COURSE.
THAT'S A DIRECT ORDER.
IN VIEW OF CODE 710,
CAPTAIN, MAY I SUGGEST--
YES, MR. SPOCK.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
CONDITION--YELLOW ALERT.
PHASER CREWS STAND BY.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS UP.
WE'RE GOING IN,
GENTLEMEN--
PEACEFULLY, I HOPE,
BUT PEACEFULLY
OR NOT...
WE'RE GOING IN.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3192.5.
NOW IN STANDARD ORBIT
AROUND PLANET EMINIAR VII.
MY ORDERS ARE CLEAR--
WE MUST ESTABLISH
DIPLOMATIC RELATIONS
AT ALL COST.
PREPARING TO BEAM DOWN
TO PLANET'S SURFACE.
WE KNOW VERY LITTLE
ABOUT THEM.
THEIR CIVILIZATION
IS ADVANCED.
THEY'VE HAD SPACEFLIGHT
FOR SEVERAL CENTURIES,
BUT THEY'VE
NEVER VENTURED BEYOND
THEIR OWN SOLAR SYSTEM.
WHEN FIRST CONTACTED
MORE THAN 50 YEARS AGO,
EMINIAR VII WAS AT WAR
WITH ITS NEAREST NEIGHBOR.
ANYTHING ELSE?
THE EARTH EXPEDITION
MAKING THE REPORT
FAILED TO RETURN
FROM ITS MISSION.
THE U.S.S. "VALIANT."
LISTED
AS MISSING IN SPACE.
KIRK, WHAT'S THIS ABOUT
YOU GOING DOWN ALONE?
NOT ALONE,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
I'M TAKING SOME
SECURITY PEOPLE
WITH ME.
IT IS MY PREROGATIVE.
I CAN'T RISK
BEAMING YOU DOWN THERE
UNTIL I KNOW WHAT
KIND OF A RECEPTION
YOU'RE GOING TO RECEIVE.
YOUR SAFETY IS MY
RESPONSIBILITY. THOSE
ARE MY ORDERS, SIR.
MR. SPOCK.
TRANSPORTER ROOM
STANDING BY, CAPTAIN.
WHAT COORDINATES?
WE'VE SELECTED A SITE
WHICH, FROM THE TRAFFIC,
WOULD SEEM TO BE NEAR
AN OFFICIAL ESTABLISHMENT.
Kirk: FINAL
SENSOR READINGS?
NO HOSTILITY
DIRECTED TOWARD US.
NO APPARENT NOTICE
TAKEN OF US AT ALL,
WHICH SEEMS STRANGE.
THEY DID SCAN US
WHEN WE ASSUMED ORBIT.
OBVIOUSLY,
THEY KNOW WE'RE HERE.
SHIP'S DEFENSES?
SCREENS DOWN,
BUT ALL DEFENSIVE DETAILS
ON GENERAL ALERT STATUS,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
THE LANDING PARTY
WILL PICK UP
PHASER NUMBER 1s
FROM THE ARSENAL.
KEEP THEM
INCONSPICUOUS.
MR. SCOTT.
YES, SIR?
THE SHIP IS YOURS.
TAKE CARE OF HER
UNTIL I COME BACK.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
AND HAVE
A BONNY TRIP.
WE'LL DO OUR BEST.
LET'S GO.
THEY WILL MATERIALIZE THERE.
REMEMBER YOUR INSTRUCTIONS.
THEY ARE TO BE TREATED
CORRECTLY, NOTHING MORE.
I'M CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE"
REPRESENTING THE UNITED
FEDERATION OF PLANETS.
I KNOW.
I'M MEA 3.
I CONGRATULATE YOU
ON YOUR INSTRUMENTATION.
YOU'VE COME DIRECTLY TO
THE DIVISION OF CONTROL.
IF YOU WILL FOLLOW ME,
PLEASE?
CAPTAIN, I WISH--
YES?
YOU WERE WARNED
NOT TO COME HERE.
I HAD ORDERS
TO COME HERE.
WHY DID YOUR PEOPLE
TELL US TO STAY AWAY?
IT WAS FOR YOUR OWN SAFETY,
CAPTAIN.
I SEE NO DANGER HERE.
THE DANGER EXISTS.
NEVERTHELESS, YOU ARE HERE.
IT WOULD BE MORALLY INCORRECT
TO DO LESS THAN EXTEND
OUR HOSPITALITY.
ANAN 7 AND MEMBERS
OF THE HIGH COUNCIL
AWAIT YOU.
IF YOU WILL COME
THIS WAY, PLEASE...
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
THIS IS
MY FIRST OFFICER,
MR. SPOCK;
LIEUTENANTS GALWAY,
OSBORNE;
YEOMAN TAMURA.
WELCOME TO EMINIAR VII.
WELL, CAPTAIN,
WHAT CAN WE DO FOR YOU?
MY MISSION IS TO ESTABLISH
DIPLOMATIC RELATIONS
BETWEEN YOUR
PEOPLE AND MINE.
THAT IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WOULD YOU MIND
TELLING ME WHY?
BECAUSE OF THE WAR.
YOU'RE STILL AT WAR?
WE HAVE BEEN AT WAR
FOR 500 YEARS.
YOU CONCEAL IT
VERY WELL.
MR. SPOCK?
SIR, WE HAVE COMPLETELY
SCANNED YOUR PLANET.
WE FIND IT HIGHLY ADVANCED,
PROSPEROUS
IN A MATERIAL SENSE,
COMFORTABLE
FOR YOUR PEOPLE,
AND PEACEFUL
IN THE EXTREME,
YET YOU SAY
YOU ARE AT WAR.
THERE IS
NO EVIDENCE OF THIS.
CASUALTIES AMONG
OUR CIVILIAN POPULATION
TOTAL FROM
1 TO 3 MILLION DEAD
EACH YEAR
FROM DIRECT ENEMY ATTACK.
THAT IS ONE REASON,
CAPTAIN,
WHY WE TOLD YOU
TO STAY AWAY.
AS LONG AS YOUR SHIP
IS ORBITING OUR PLANET,
IT IS IN SEVERE DANGER.
WITH WHOM
ARE YOU AT WAR?
THE THIRD PLANET
IN OUR SYSTEM,
CALLED VENDIKAR,
ORIGINALLY SETTLED
BY OUR PEOPLE
AND NOW
A RUTHLESS ENEMY--
HIGHLY ADVANCED
TECHNOLOGICALLY.
[ALARM BUZZING]
PLEASE EXCUSE ME.
VENDIKAR IS ATTACKING.
MEA, PREPARE
FOR OUR GUESTS.
STRANGE.
TO SAY THE LEAST.
IT WILL NOT
LAST LONG.
DON'T YOU
TAKE SHELTER?
THERE IS
NO SHELTER, CAPTAIN.
ARE THESE ATTACKS
FREQUENT?
OH, YES, AND WE WILL
RETALIATE IMMEDIATELY.
OH!
Kirk:
WHAT IS IT?
A HIT RIGHT HERE
IN THE CITY.
DO YOU HEAR
ANY EXPLOSIONS,
MR. SPOCK?
NONE, CAPTAIN.
YEOMAN TAMURA?
SIR?
TRICORDER READINGS--
RADIATION DISTURBANCES
OF ANY KIND.
[BUZZING]
WORKING, SIR.
NO EVIDENCE.
MEA...
IF THIS IS AN ATTACK,
MAY I ASK WHAT WEAPONS
THE ENEMY IS USING?
FUSION BOMBS,
MATERIALIZED BY THE ENEMY
OVER THEIR TARGETS.
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
SCOTTY?
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
SCANNERS OPERATIVE
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE?
OF COURSE, SIR.
AS PER ORDERS.
ANYTHING UNUSUAL?
NOTHING, SIR.
ALL QUIET.
THANK YOU.
KIRK OUT.
LOOK, ANAN.
YES, I SEE IT.
THEY WERE WARNED.
JUST AS IT HAPPENED
50 YEARS AGO.
ALERT A SECURITY
DETACHMENT.
THEY MAY BE NEEDED.
IT WAS
A VICIOUS ATTACK--
EXTREMELY DESTRUCTIVE.
FORTUNATELY,
OUR DEFENSES ARE FIRMING,
BUT OUR CASUALTIES
ARE HIGH--
VERY HIGH.
SIR, I HAVE BEEN
IN CONTACT WITH MY SHIP,
WHICH HAS HAD
THIS ENTIRE PLANET
UNDER SURVEILLANCE.
ALL DURING THIS...
SO-CALLED ATTACK,
WE HAVE BEEN
MONITORING.
THERE'S BEEN
NO ATTACK,
NO EXPLOSIONS,
NO RADIATIONS,
NO DISTURBANCES
WHATSOEVER.
IF THIS IS
SOME SORT OF GAME
YOU'RE PLAYING--
THIS IS NO GAME,
CAPTAIN.
HALF A MILLION PEOPLE
HAVE JUST BEEN KILLED.
ACTIVATE THE ATTACK
UNITS, SAR.
YES, COUNCILMAN.
LAUNCH IMMEDIATE
COUNTERATTACK.
COMPUTERS, CAPTAIN.
THEY FIGHT THEIR WAR
WITH COMPUTERS TOTALLY.
YES, OF COURSE.
COMPUTERS DON'T KILL
A HALF A MILLION PEOPLE.
DEATHS HAVE
BEEN REGISTERED.
OF COURSE, THEY HAVE
24 HOURS TO REPORT.
TO REPORT?
TO OUR DISINTEGRATION
MACHINES.
YOU MUST UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN,
WE HAVE BEEN AT WAR
FOR 500 YEARS.
UNDER ORDINARY CONDITIONS,
NO CIVILIZATION
COULD WITHSTAND THAT,
BUT WE HAVE REACHED
A SOLUTION.
THEN THE ATTACK
BY VENDIKAR
WAS THEORETICAL.
OH, NO. QUITE REAL.
AN ATTACK IS
MATHEMATICALLY LAUNCHED.
I LOST MY WIFE
IN THE LAST ATTACK.
OUR CIVILIZATION LIVES.
THE PEOPLE DIE,
BUT OUR CULTURE
GOES ON.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME...
YOUR PEOPLE JUST WALK INTO
A DISINTEGRATION MACHINE
WHEN THEY'RE TOLD TO?
WE HAVE A HIGH
CONSCIOUSNESS OF
DUTY, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS A CERTAIN
SCIENTIFIC LOGIC
ABOUT IT.
I'M GLAD YOU APPROVE.
I DO NOT APPROVE.
I UNDERSTAND.
GOOD.
AND YOU WILL RECALL,
I WARNED YOU
NOT TO COME HERE.
YOU CHOSE
TO IGNORE MY WARNING.
I'M SORRY,
BUT IT'S HAPPENED.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED?
ONCE YOUR SHIP WAS IN ORBIT
ABOUT OUR PLANET,
IT BECAME
A LEGITIMATE TARGET.
IT HAS BEEN
CLASSIFIED DESTROYED
BY A TRICOBALT
SATELLITE EXPLOSION.
ALL PERSONS
ABOARD YOUR SHIP
HAVE 24 HOURS TO REPORT
TO OUR DISINTEGRATION
MACHINES.
IN ORDER TO ENSURE
THEIR COOPERATION,
I HAVE ORDERED YOU,
CAPTAIN, AND YOUR PARTY
HELD IN CUSTODY
UNTIL THEY SURRENDER.
IF POSSIBLE, WE SHALL
SPARE YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN,
BUT ITS PASSENGERS AND CREW
ARE ALREADY DEAD.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, DELAYED.
THE "ENTERPRISE,"
IN ORBIT ABOUT EMINIAR VII,
HAS BEEN DECLARED
A CASUALTY
OF AN INCREDIBLE WAR
FOUGHT BY COMPUTERS.
I AND MY LANDING PARTY,
THOUGH APPARENTLY
NOT INCLUDED
AS CASUALTIES
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE,
ARE CONFINED
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE
AWAITING...
WHAT?
I HAVE BEEN SENT
TO ASK IF YOU
REQUIRE ANYTHING.
WE REQUIRE A GREAT DEAL.
I WISH TO SPEAK
TO ANAN 7.
HE IS BUSY COORDINATING
CASUALTY LISTS.
HE'LL HAVE MORE
CASUALTY LISTS
THAN HE KNOWS
WHAT TO DO WITH
IF HE DOESN'T GET IN HERE
AND TALK TO ME.
DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND?
OUR DUTY NOW--
YOUR DUTY
DOESN'T INCLUDE
STEPPING INTO
A DISINTEGRATOR
AND DISAPPEARING.
I'M AFRAID MINE DOES,
CAPTAIN.
I, TOO, HAVE BEEN
DECLARED A CASUALTY.
I MUST REPORT
TO A DISINTEGRATOR
BY NOON TOMORROW.
IS THAT ALL
IT MEANS TO YOU?
TO REPORT AND DIE?
MY LIFE IS AS DEAR TO ME
AS YOURS IS TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
THEN HOW
CAN YOU STAND--
DON'T YOU SEE?
IF I REFUSE TO REPORT,
AND OTHERS REFUSE,
THEN VENDIKAR
WOULD HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO LAUNCH
REAL WEAPONS.
WE WOULD HAVE TO
DO THE SAME
TO DEFEND OURSELVES.
MORE THAN PEOPLE
WOULD DIE THEN.
A WHOLE CIVILIZATION
WOULD BE DESTROYED.
SURELY YOU CAN SEE THAT
OURS IS THE BETTER WAY.
NO...I DON'T
SEE THAT AT ALL.
IT'S BEEN OUR WAY
FOR ALMOST 500 YEARS.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN BRING YOU?
YES. ANON 7.
I TELL YOU, WE SHOULD HAVE
HEARD SOMETHING BY NOW.
AYE, DOCTOR,
THAT WE SHOULD,
BUT WE HAVEN'T,
AND WE CANNOT
RAISE THEM.
NOW, IF THERE'D
BEEN TROUBLE,
THEY SHOULD HAVE
AT LEAST MANAGED
TO GET WORD
BACK TO US.
WE CAN'T JUST SIT HERE.
WHAT WOULD YOU SUGGEST?
ME? I'M A DOCTOR.
IF I WERE AN OFFICER
OF THE LINE, I'D--
WOULD YOU HAVE ME
OPEN FIRE?
OF COURSE NOT.
MR. SCOTT,
MESSAGE COMING IN
FROM THE CAPTAIN.
SCOTT HERE,
CAPTAIN.
Kirk's voice:
GOOD NEWS, MR. SCOTT.
THE EMINIANS HAVE AGREED
TO THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF FULL NORMAL
DIPLOMATIC RELATIONS.
MR. FOX WILL BE GLAD
TO HEAR ABOUT THAT.
THEY'VE ALSO EXTENDED
AN INVITATION
TO ALL PERSONNEL
TO COME ASHORE
FOR SHORE LEAVE.
THEY'VE ASSURED ME
THAT OUR PEOPLE WILL
HAVE A WONDERFUL TIME.
UH, CAPTAIN?
YES, MR. SCOTT?
ALL PERSONNEL?
ALL PERSONNEL.
WE'LL TRANSPORT UP
TRAINED EMINIANS
TO ASSUME
SUPPORT POSITIONS.
THOSE ARE MY ORDERS,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
WE'LL START FORMING
SHORE PARTIES
IMMEDIATELY.
SCOTT OUT.
WELL, NOW, WHAT DO
YOU THINK OF THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, I DO.
COMPUTER,
LAST MESSAGE
RECEIVED AND RECORDED
FROM CAPTAIN KIRK.
[COMPUTER WHIRS]
IN PLACE.
RUN IT THROUGH ANALYZER.
QUESTION--
IS IT OR IS IT NOT
THE CAPTAIN'S VOICE?
NEGATIVE.
A CLOSE COPY.
A VOICE DUPLICATOR?
98% PROBABILITY.
WELL, THEY'VE GOT THEM,
DOCTOR,
AND NOW THEY'RE TRYING
TO GET US.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU CAN DO IT,
MR. SPOCK?
LIMITED
TELEPATHIC ABILITIES
ARE INHERENT
IN VULCANIANS, CAPTAIN.
IT MAY WORK.
IT MAY NOT.
DO YOUR BEST.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
MY PLEASURE,
CAPTAIN.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW,
CAPTAIN?
WE GET OUR
COMMUNICATORS BACK
AND TRY AND CONTACT
THE SHIP.
MR. SPOCK,
WE'LL NEED MORE WEAPONS.
I UNDERSTAND.
WE'LL TRY TO TAKE IT EASY,
BUT IF WE'RE
FORCED TO KILL...
AN ENTRANCE, CAPTAIN,
BUT NO EXIT.
THEY GO IN,
BUT THEY DO NOT COME OUT.
A DISINTEGRATION
MACHINE.
SO I WOULD ASSUME.
MEA!
OH!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
I'M--I'M GOING--
YOU'RE NOT GOING
IN THERE.
WELL, I MUST.
NO,
YOU'RE NOT.
PLEASE--DON'T
WORRY ABOUT ME.
MR. SPOCK, THAT GUARD.
I'LL COVER YOU.
SIR, THERE'S
A MULTILEGGED CREATURE
CRAWLING ON YOUR SHOULDER.
ALL RIGHT, YOU PEOPLE,
CLEAR OUT OF THE WAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
THROWING A MONKEY WRENCH
INTO THE MACHINERY.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
I'VE DONE IT.
COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
Man: THE FEDERATION
PRISONERS HAVE ATTACKED
THEIR GUARD AND ESCAPED.
THEY ARE ARMED.
DISINTEGRATION STATION
NUMBER 12 DESTROYED,
COUNCILMAN,
APPARENTLY
BY DISRUPTOR FIRE.
ALL SECURITY PERSONNEL,
FEDERATION PRISONERS
HAVE ESCAPED.
THEY ARE TO BE FOUND.
THEY ARE ARMED.
IF THEY RESIST,
DO WHAT IS NECESSARY.
PLANETARY DISRUPTOR BANKS,
CALCULATE ORBIT OF
STARCRUISER NOW CIRCLING.
STAND BY TO FIRE
FULL POWER.
Computer: COUNCILMAN,
PLANETARY DISRUPTOR BANKS
LOCKED ONTO TARGET.
STANDING BY.
IN 10 SECONDS,
OPEN FIRE.
DESTROY THE STARCRUISER.
THOSE ARE THE ORDERS
OF THE COUNCIL.
Scotty: SHIP'S LOG.
STARDATE 3193.0--
CHIEF ENGINEER SCOTT
RECORDING.
THE CAPTAIN
AND FIRST OFFICER
ARE OVERDUE AND MISSING
ON THE SURFACE OF EMINIAR 7.
I HAVE TAKEN STANDARD
PRECAUTIONARY MEASURES
WHILE WE CONTINUE OUR
ATTEMPTS TO LOCATE THEM.
ALL STATIONS REPORTING.
DEFLECTOR SCREENS
RIGGED AT FULL POWER.
PHASER CREWS READY.
SENSORS READING 0.
CORRECTION.
MR. SCOTT.
YES, MR. DePAUL?
SENSOR READINGS JUST
SHOT OFF THE SCALE.
WELL, NOW...
THEY'RE TAKING
POTSHOTS AT US.
HOLDING, MR. DePAUL?
SCREENS FIRM, SIR.
EXTREMELY POWERFUL
SONIC VIBRATIONS.
DECIBELS--
18 TO THE 12th POWER.
IF THOSE SCREENS
WEREN'T UP,
WE'D BE TOTALLY
DISRUPTED BY NOW.
I GUESS THAT ANSWERS
OUR QUESTIONS,
MR. SCOTT.
THEY'RE NOT
VERY FRIENDLY,
ARE THEY?
AYE.
BUT WHAT ABOUT
OUR CAPTAIN
AND THE LANDING PARTY
DOWN THERE SOMEWHERE?
WE GET THEM OUT.
IF THEY'RE ALIVE
AND IF WE CAN FIND THEM.
THAT'S A BIG PLANET.
NOT TOO BIG FOR
THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO HANDLE
IF IT HAS TO.
WE CAN'T FIRE FULL PHASERS
WITH OUR SCREENS UP.
WE CAN'T LOWER OUR SCREENS
WITH THEIR DISRUPTORS
ON US.
OF COURSE,
I COULD TREAT THEM
TO A FEW DOZEN
PHOTON TORPEDOES.
YOU WILL DO
NO SUCH THING,
MR. SCOTT.
MR. FOX,
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
THEY'RE TRYING
TO KNOCK US DOWN.
YOU HAVE TAKEN
DEFENSIVE MEASURES.
OF COURSE, BUT--
THERE ARE NO BUTS.
OBVIOUSLY IT'S
A MISUNDERSTANDING,
AND ONE OF MY JOBS
IS TO CLEAR UP
MISUNDERSTANDINGS.
THEY'RE HOLDING
OUR CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE NO PROOF
OF THAT.
I AM RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE SAFETY OF THIS SHIP.
AND I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE SUCCESS
OF THIS MISSION,
AND THAT'S MORE IMPORTANT
THAN THIS SHIP.
IS THAT CLEAR?
WE CAME HERE TO ESTABLISH
DIPLOMATIC RELATIONS
WITH THESE PEOPLE.
BUT THEY'RE THE ONES
THAT ARE LOOKING FOR
A FIGHT, MR. FOX.
THIS IS
A DIPLOMATIC MATTER.
IF YOU'LL CHECK
YOUR REGULATIONS,
YOU'LL FIND THAT
MY ORDERS GET PRIORITY.
I'LL TRY
TO MAKE CONTACT
WITH THE PLANETARY
OFFICIALS.
LIEUTENANT,
OPEN UP A CHANNEL
AND KEEP IT OPEN.
TELL THEM TO EXPECT
A PRIORITY-1 MESSAGE FROM ME.
THERE WILL BE NO PUNITIVE
MEASURES, GENTLEMEN.
THOSE ARE MY ORDERS.
DIPLOMATS.
THE BEST DIPLOMAT I KNOW
IS A FULLY-ACTIVATED
PHASER BANK.
WHY DID WE COME BACK HERE,
CAPTAIN?
THE LAST PLACE
THEY'LL LOOK
FOR US
IS THE PLACE
WE ESCAPED FROM.
COVER THE DOOR.
CAPTAIN, YOU HAVE GOT
TO LET ME GO.
MY TIME IS ALMOST UP.
ARE YOU THAT ANXIOUS
TO DIE?
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
MR. SPOCK,
HOW DID THAT
LITTLE RAID WORK OUT?
WE CAPTURED 4 OF THEIR
DISRUPTOR-TYPE WEAPONS,
TWO COMPLETE OUTFITS
OF MALE CLOTHING,
AND, PERHAPS
MOST IMPORTANT OF ALL,
ONE OF THEIR
COMMUNICATION DEVICES.
WILL IT REACH THE SHIP?
NOT AT THIS TIME.
ITS RANGE IS RESTRICTED
IN COMPARISON WITH OURS.
I MAY BE ABLE TO ALTER
ITS COMPONENTS,
BUT IT WILL
TAKE TIME.
GET TO WORK ON IT.
WE'VE GOT TO CONTACT
THE SHIP.
MEA, I WANT YOU
TO GIVE ME
A COMPLETE LAYOUT
OF THIS BUILDING COMPLEX.
HOW DO I GET
TO THE WAR ROOM?
NO.
NOW, LISTEN TO ME.
I'M TRYING TO HELP YOU,
TO SAVE YOUR LIFE
AND THE LIVES OF
MILLIONS LIKE YOU.
IF YOU HELP ME,
MAYBE I CAN DO IT.
IF YOU DON'T,
YOU'LL DIE,
WE'LL DIE, AND THE KILLING
WILL GO ON--
OR ARE YOU THAT FOND
OF THE WAR?
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
WE'RE GOING TO TRY
AND STOP THE KILLING.
WE'RE TRYING TO HELP.
BELIEVE ME.
I BELIEVE YOU, BUT--
TELL ME
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW.
PLEASE.
TIME IS RUNNING OUT.
WE HAVE BEEN UNABLE
TO DESTROY THE EARTH SHIP,
ONE OF OUR
DISINTEGRATION CHAMBERS
HAS BEEN ELIMINATED,
AND WE HAVE ALREADY FALLEN
FAR BEHIND IN OUR QUOTA.
THIS IS A GRAVE CRISIS,
AND I AM AT A LOSS
TO KNOW HOW TO PROCEED.
THE CENTRAL CHANNEL,
ANAN.
THE EARTH
AMBASSADOR'S CALLING
WITH
AN URGENT MESSAGE.
WHAT IS
THE GREATER MORALITY,
OPEN HONESTY
OR A DECEPTION
WHICH MAY SAVE OUR LIVES?
PUT ME THROUGH
TO THE EARTH AMBASSADOR.
A CHANNEL IS OPEN,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
YOU WILL BE SPEAKING
TO ANAN 7,
HEAD OF THE HIGH COUNCIL
OF THE EMINIAN UNION.
[BEEP]
MR. ANAN,
THIS IS ROBERT FOX,
SPECIAL AMBASSADOR FOR THE
UNITED FEDERATION OF PLANETS.
A GREAT HONOR,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
WE HAVE
APPROACHED YOU OPENLY,
WITH THE INTENT
OF ESTABLISHING FORMAL
AND FRIENDLY RELATIONS
BETWEEN OUR PEOPLES,
BUT NOW, FOR SOME REASON,
YOU HAVE ATTACKED US,
AND APPARENTLY
YOU'RE HOLDING SEVERAL
SPECIAL REPRESENTATIVES
OF OUR FEDERATION.
A MISTAKE,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
WE ARE AT WAR.
AN ERROR IN OUR SENSORS
INDICATED THAT YOUR SHIP
WAS ABOUT TO ATTACK US.
I AM GIVING ORDERS THAT
OUR ATTACK BE STOPPED.
NOW, AS TO
YOUR REPRESENTATIVES,
YOU HAVE MY SACRED WORD
AS AN EMINIAN
THAT THEY ARE
ALIVE AND WELL.
THANK YOU.
I THOUGHT PERHAPS
IT WAS ALL A MISTAKE.
MR. SCOTT,
DISRUPTOR BEAMS ARE
NO LONGER HITTING US.
MAINTAIN STATUS,
MR. DePAUL.
WE ARE MOST ANXIOUS
TO ESTABLISH RELATIONS
WITH YOU, MR. FOX.
WE WILL MAKE
ARRANGEMENTS
TO RECEIVE YOU.
THE MINUTE THEIR SCREENS
ARE DOWN, OPEN FIRE.
YES, COUNCILMAN.
I APOLOGIZE DEEPLY FOR
THE MISUNDERSTANDING.
THESE ARE TRYING TIMES
FOR US, YOU UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND.
MR. ANAN, I PRESUME
THAT YOU WILL HAVE
OUR SHIP'S CAPTAIN ON HAND
WHEN I BEAM DOWN.
HE WILL BE THERE, SIR.
I GIVE YOU MY WORD.
I'M SURE THAT FROM
THIS DAY FORWARD,
YOUR PLANET
AND OUR FEDERATION
WILL ATTAIN
THE DEEPEST FRIENDSHIP.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO SEEING YOU.
DIPLOMACY, GENTLEMEN,
SHOULD BE
A JOB LEFT TO DIPLOMATS.
YOU WILL, OF COURSE,
IMMEDIATELY RESUME
A PEACEFUL STATUS.
NO, SIR, I WILL NOT.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I'LL NOT
LOWER THE SCREENS,
NOT UNTIL THE CAPTAIN
TELLS ME TO.
YOU ARE TAKING ORDERS
FROM ME.
YOU WILL LOWER THE
SCREENS AS A SIGN
OF GOOD FAITH.
MY AUTHORITY.
I KNOW ABOUT
YOUR AUTHORITY,
BUT THE SCREENS
STAY UP.
MR. FOX,
THEY FAKED A MESSAGE
FROM THE CAPTAIN,
THEY'VE
LAUNCHED AN ATTACK
AGAINST OUR SHIP.
NOW, YOU WANT US TO
TRUST THEM OPENLY?
I WANT YOU AND EXPECT YOU
TO OBEY MY LAWFUL ORDERS.
NO, SIR. I WON'T
LOWER THE SCREENS.
YOUR REFUSAL TO COMPLY
WITH MY ORDERS
HAS ENDANGERED THE ENTIRE
SUCCESS OF THIS MISSION!
I CAN HAVE YOU SENT
TO A PENAL COLONY FOR THIS.
THAT YOU CAN, SIR,
BUT I WON'T
LOWER THE SCREENS.
YOUR NAME
WILL FIGURE PROMINENTLY
IN MY REPORT
TO THE FEDERATION CENTRAL.
WELL, SCOTTY,
NOW YOU'VE DONE IT.
AYE. THE HAGGIS IS
IN THE FIRE FOR SURE,
BUT I'LL NOT
LOWER MY DEFENSES
ON THE WORD OF THAT
MEALY-MOUTHED GENTLEMAN
DOWN BELOW,
NOT UNTIL I KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE CAPTAIN.
WON'T YOU JOIN ME
IN A DRINK, CAPTAIN?
YOU'LL FIND OUR TROVA
MOST INTERESTING.
I DIDN'T COME TO DRINK.
I ASSUME
THAT IS WHAT YOU USED
TO DESTROY
DISINTEGRATION CHAMBER 12.
A VERY EFFICIENT WEAPON.
I'M NOT AFRAID
OF USING IT.
MY FIRST IMPRESSION
WAS CORRECT.
YOU ARE A BARBARIAN.
I AM?
DON'T SOUND
SO INCREDULOUS, CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE YOU ARE.
WE ALL ARE.
A KILLER FIRST,
A BUILDER SECOND.
A HUNTER, A WARRIOR,
AND--LET'S BE HONEST--
A MURDERER.
THAT IS OUR JOINT HERITAGE,
IS IT NOT?
WE'RE A LITTLE LESS
COLD-BLOODED ABOUT IT
THAN YOU ARE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT,
CAPTAIN?
I WANT TO
CONTACT MY SHIP.
WHERE ARE
MY COMMUNICATORS?
IN A SAFE PLACE.
YOU TAKE A LOT OF
CHANCES, COUNCILMAN.
YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT
YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN.
I'M TRYING
TO SAVE A WORLD.
IF I WERE YOU,
I'D THINK ABOUT
SAVING MY LIFE.
WON'T YOU HAVE A DRINK,
CAPTAIN?
AND THEN WE CAN DISCUSS
OUR DIFFERENCES.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN DISCUSSING
OUR DIFFERENCES.
YOU DON'T SEEM TO
REALIZE THE RISK
YOU'RE TAKING.
WE DON'T MAKE WAR
WITH COMPUTERS
AND HERD THE CASUALTIES
INTO SUICIDE STATIONS.
WE MAKE THE REAL THING,
COUNCILMAN.
I COULD DESTROY
THIS PLANET.
WHY DO YOU THINK
I DON'T LET YOU
TALK TO YOUR SHIP?
I DON'T NEED THE SHIP
FOR THAT.
YOU MEAN,
ALL BY YOURSELF,
WITH A DISRUPTOR,
YOU CAN DESTROY
THIS PLANET?
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I MEAN.
I HAD NO IDEA YOU WERE
SO...FORMIDABLE.
YOU SEEM TO THINK
I'M JOKING.
WHERE ARE
THE COMMUNICATORS?
IF I TOLD YOU,
CAPTAIN,
WOULD YOU
WALK RIGHT OUT
AND GET THEM?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE IN THE WAR ROOM.
GO LEFT,
DOWN THE CORRIDOR,
LEFT AGAIN.
THEY ARE UNGUARDED.
IS HE ALIVE?
PITY.
A MAN LIKE THAT WOULD'VE...
PREFERRED TO DIE FIGHTING.
TAKE HIM
TO THE COUNCIL ROOM.
AMBASSADOR FOX?
I AM ROBERT FOX.
HAVE I THE HONOR
OF ADDRESSING
ANAN 7?
WELCOME TO EMINIAR,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
UH, MR. AMBASSADOR,
I AM TRULY SORRY FOR
WHAT MUST HAPPEN.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
YOU AND YOUR PARTY
HAVE BEEN DECLARED
WAR CASUALTIES.
YOU'LL BE TAKEN
IMMEDIATELY TO ONE OF
OUR CASUALTY STATIONS
SO THAT YOUR DEATHS
MAY BE RECORDED.
YOU MEAN...
WE ARE TO BE KILLED?
THAT IS CORRECT,
MR. AMBASSADOR.
I REGRET IT
VERY MUCH,
BUT THERE IS NOTHING
I CAN DO ABOUT IT.
[BEEPING]
SPOCK TO "ENTERPRISE."
COME IN.
MR. SCOTT,
IT'S MR. SPOCK.
SCOTTY HERE,
MR. SPOCK. GO AHEAD.
IS THE SHIP
ALL RIGHT?
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
A BIT, BUT WE'RE
ALL RIGHT NOW.
HOW ABOUT
THE CAPTAIN AND YOU?
THE CAPTAIN IS OVERDUE.
WE'VE SUFFERED
NO CASUALTIES AMONG US.
THIS IS IMPORTANT--
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
SHALL ANYONE BEAM DOWN
FROM THE "ENTERPRISE."
THEY'D BE KILLED
THE MOMENT THEY ARRIVED.
THAT TIES IT. THAT
POPINJAY FOX WENT DOWN
A COUPLE OF MINUTES AGO.
THE AMBASSADOR.
I KNEW IT HAD
A ROTTEN RING TO IT.
ORBIT OUT TO MAXIMUM
PHASER RANGE
AND STAND BY
FOR FURTHER ORDERS.
SPOCK OUT.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO, MR. SPOCK?
FIND THE AMBASSADOR
AND THE CAPTAIN.
YEOMAN TAMURA,
YOU STAY HERE
AND PREVENT
THIS YOUNG LADY
FROM IMMOLATING HERSELF.
KNOCK HER DOWN
AND SIT ON HER
IF NECESSARY.
THIS IS A KILLING
SITUATION.
DO WHAT YOU MUST
TO PROTECT YOURSELF.
CLEAR?
YES, SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M A REPRESENTATIVE
OF THE UNITED FEDERATION
OF PLANETS!
A SPECIAL
REPRESENTATIVE!
GET IN LINE.
SPOCK!
PLEASE, MR. FOX.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
PLEASE MOVE QUICKLY AWAY
FROM THE CHAMBER,
OR YOU MAY BE INJURED.
[BEEPING]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
MR. SPOCK?
PRACTICING
A PECULIAR VARIETY
OF DIPLOMACY, SIR.
I'LL TAKE YOU TO A PLACE
OF COMPARATIVE SAFETY.
THEN I MUST
FIND THE CAPTAIN.
THEY HAVE HIM.
THE GUARDS TOLD US.
THEY TOOK HIM
TO THE COUNCIL ROOM
UNDER HEAVY GUARD.
BY NOW, MR. AMBASSADOR,
I'M SURE YOU REALIZE
THAT NORMAL
DIPLOMATIC PROCEDURES
ARE INEFFECTIVE HERE.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
A SOLDIER, MR. SPOCK,
BUT I LEARN
VERY QUICKLY.
VERY WELL, SIR. WE NEED
ALL THE HELP WE CAN GET.
Anan 7: CAPTAIN,
SURELY YOU CAN SEE
THE POSITION WE ARE IN.
IF YOUR PEOPLE
DO NOT REPORT TO OUR
DISINTEGRATION CHAMBERS,
IT IS A VIOLATION
OF AN AGREEMENT
THAT DATES BACK
500 YEARS.
MY PEOPLE
ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE
FOR YOUR AGREEMENTS.
YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR AN ESCALATION
THAT WILL DESTROY
EVERYTHING.
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HORRIBLY KILLED,
COMPLETE DESTRUCTION
OF OUR CULTURE HERE--
YES, AND THE CULTURE
ON VENDIKAR--
DISASTER, DISEASE,
STARVATION,
HORRIBLE,
LINGERING DEATH,
PAIN AND ANGUISH!
THAT SEEMS
TO FRIGHTEN YOU.
IT WOULD FRIGHTEN
ANY SANE MAN.
YES. YOU'RE
QUITE RIGHT.
DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND, CAPTAIN?
WE HAVE DONE AWAY
WITH ALL THAT.
NOW YOU ARE THREATENING
TO BRING IT DOWN
ON US AGAIN.
ARE THOSE 500 PEOPLE
OF YOURS
MORE IMPORTANT THAN
THE HUNDREDS OF MILLIONS
OF INNOCENT PEOPLE
ON EMINIAR AND VENDIKAR?
WHAT KIND OF MONSTER
ARE YOU?
I'M A BARBARIAN.
YOU SAID IT
YOURSELF.
I HAD HOPED I HAD SPOKEN
ONLY FIGURATIVELY.
OH, NO. YOU WERE
QUITE ACCURATE.
I PLAN
TO PROVE IT TO YOU.
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO THE "ENTERPRISE."
YOU GIVE ME NO CHOICE,
CAPTAIN.
WE ARE NOT BANDITS,
BUT YOU FORCE US
TO ACT AS BANDITS.
Scotty: THIS IS
THE U.S.S. "ENTERPRISE."
SCOTTY, GENERAL
ORDER 24 IN 2 HOURS!
IN 2 HOURS!
"ENTERPRISE"...
THIS IS ANAN 7,
FIRST COUNCILMAN
OF THE HIGH COUNCIL
OF EMINIAR.
WE HOLD YOUR CAPTAIN,
HIS PARTY,
YOUR AMBASSADOR,
AND HIS PARTY
PRISONERS.
UNLESS YOU IMMEDIATELY
START TRANSPORTATION
OF ALL PERSONNEL
ABOARD YOUR SHIP
TO THE SURFACE,
THE HOSTAGES
WILL BE KILLED.
YOU HAVE 30 MINUTES.
I MEAN IT, CAPTAIN.
ALL THAT MEANS IS THAT
I WON'T BE AROUND
FOR THE DESTRUCTION.
YOU HEARD ME GIVE
GENERAL ORDER 24.
THAT MEANS IN TWO HOURS,
THE "ENTERPRISE" WILL
DESTROY EMINIAR VII.
PLANETARY DEFENSE SYSTEM,
OPEN FIRE
ON THE "ENTERPRISE."
I'M SORRY,
COUNCILMAN.
THE TARGET HAS
MOVED OUT OF RANGE.
YOU WOULDN'T DO THIS.
HUNDREDS OF MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE.
I DIDN'T START IT,
COUNCILMAN...
BUT I'M LIABLE
TO FINISH IT.
COUNCILMAN, RECEIVED
A MESSAGE FROM VENDIKAR.
OUR TIME IS NEARLY UP.
OUR QUOTA IS SHORT
BY SEVERAL THOUSAND.
THEY ACCUSE US
OF RENEGING
ON THE TREATY.
YOU SEE?
IT'S STARTED.
YOU'RE WRONG.
IT HASN'T BEGUN.
Computer: COUNCILMAN,
DISINTEGRATOR STATION 11
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
GUARDS POSITIONED
AT TUNNELS 8 AND 10
FAIL TO ANSWER.
EARTH PARTY REPORTED SEEN
IN CORRIDOR 4-A.
YOU HAVE
LESS THAN TWO HOURS,
COUNCILMAN.
WHAT I WANT OR DON'T WANT
HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
ESCALATION IS AUTOMATIC.
YOU CAN STOP IT!
STOP IT?
I'M COUNTING ON IT.
OPEN A CHANNEL,
LIEUTENANT.
[BEEP]
THIS IS THE COMMANDER
OF THE U.S.S. "ENTERPRISE."
ALL CITIES AND INSTALLATIONS
ON EMINIAR VII
HAVE BEEN LOCATED,
IDENTIFIED,
AND FED INTO
OUR FIRE CONTROL SYSTEM.
IN 1 HOUR AND 45 MINUTES,
THE ENTIRE INHABITED SURFACE
OF YOUR PLANET
WILL BE DESTROYED.
YOU HAVE THAT LONG
TO SURRENDER YOUR HOSTAGES.
WHAT CAN I DO?
SOMEBODY,
PLEASE TELL ME.
HOLD IT!
OVER THERE.
YOU, OVER THERE.
MOVE, MOVE, MOVE.
NOW WE'LL TALK.
I HAD ASSUMED
YOU NEEDED HELP.
I SEE I'M IN ERROR.
NO, I NEED THE HELP.
IN THERE, MR. SPOCK.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
COME IN, SCOTTY.
AYE, CAPTAIN.,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
EVERYTHING'S
SECURE HERE.
MAINTAIN POSITION.
IF EVERYTHING GOES
ACCORDING TO PLAN,
YOU CAN BEAM US UP
IN 10 MINUTES.
IF YOU DON'T HEAR FROM US,
CARRY OUT GENERAL ORDER 24
ON SCHEDULE.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
WE CAN DO?
CROSS YOUR FINGERS.
KIRK OUT.
DEATH...
DESTRUCTION,
DISEASE, HORROR...
THAT'S WHAT WAR
IS ALL ABOUT, ANAN.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT
A THING TO BE AVOIDED.
YOU'VE MADE IT
NEAT AND PAINLESS--
SO NEAT AND PAINLESS,
YOU'VE HAD NO REASON
TO STOP IT.
AND YOU'VE HAD IT
FOR 500 YEARS.
SINCE IT SEEMS TO BE
THE ONLY WAY
I CAN SAVE
MY CREW AND MY SHIP,
I'M GOING TO
END IT FOR YOU,
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
MR. AMBASSADOR.
YES, CAPTAIN.
WOULD YOU MIND TAKING THESE
PEOPLE OUT INTO THE CORRIDOR
AND HOLDING THEM THERE?
GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU PLEASE.
YOU...
COME WITH ME.
MR. OSBORNE.
OUR COMMUNICATORS,
WEAPONS.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
THESE ARE
THE ATTACK COMPUTERS,
CAPTAIN.
THAT ONE'S DEFENSE,
THAT ONE
COMPUTES THE CASUALTIES.
THEY'RE ALL TIED IN
WITH A SUBSPACE
TRANSMISSION UNIT
WHICH KEEPS THEM
IN CONSTANT CONTACT
WITH THEIR VENDIKAN
COUNTERPARTS.
YES, GO ON.
THE MOMENT
CONTACT IS BROKEN,
IT ABROGATES
THE AGREEMENT
BETWEEN THE TWO
WARRING PARTIES.
WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO?
THIS ONE'S THE KEY.
THE CIRCUIT
IS NOW LOCKED.
DESTROY THIS ONE,
AND THEY'LL ALL GO.
GOOD. GET HIM
OUT OF HERE.
NO. WAIT A MINUTE!
PLEASE, PLEASE!
LET'S GO.
AGAINST THE WALLS!
DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE?
YES, I DO.
I'VE GIVEN YOU BACK
THE HORRORS OF WAR.
THE VENDIKANS WILL
NOW ASSUME THAT YOU'VE
BROKEN YOUR AGREEMENT
AND THAT YOU'RE
PREPARING TO WAGE REAL
WAR WITH REAL WEAPONS.
THEY'LL WANT
TO DO THE SAME,
ONLY THE NEXT ATTACK
THEY LAUNCH
WILL DO A LOT MORE
THAN JUST COUNT UP
NUMBERS IN A COMPUTER.
THEY'LL DESTROY YOUR CITIES,
DEVASTATE YOUR PLANET.
YOU, OF COURSE,
WILL WANT TO RETALIATE.
IF I WERE YOU,
I'D START MAKING BOMBS.
YES, COUNCILMAN,
YOU HAVE A REAL WAR
ON YOUR HANDS.
YOU CAN EITHER WAGE IT
WITH REAL WEAPONS,
OR YOU MIGHT CONSIDER
AN ALTERNATIVE--
PUT AN END TO IT.
MAKE PEACE.
THERE CAN BE NO PEACE.
DON'T YOU SEE?
WE'VE ADMITTED IT
TO OURSELVES.
WE'RE A KILLER SPECIES.
IT'S INSTINCTIVE.
IT'S THE SAME WITH YOU,
YOUR GENERAL ORDER 24.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S INSTINCTIVE.
BUT THE INSTINCT
CAN BE FOUGHT.
WE'RE HUMAN BEINGS
WITH THE BLOOD OF A MILLION
SAVAGE YEARS ON OUR HANDS,
BUT WE CAN STOP IT.
WE CAN ADMIT
THAT WE'RE KILLERS,
BUT WE'RE NOT
GOING TO KILL TODAY.
THAT'S ALL IT TAKES--
KNOWING THAT WE'RE NOT
GOING TO KILL TODAY.
CONTACT VENDIKAR.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
THAT THEY'RE JUST AS
TERRIFIED, APPALLED,
HORRIFIED AS YOU ARE,
THAT THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
TO AVOID THE ALTERNATIVE
I'VE GIVEN YOU.
PEACE OR UTTER DESTRUCTION.
IT'S UP TO YOU.
AS A THIRD PARTY,
INTERESTED ONLY
IN PEACE
AND THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF NORMAL RELATIONS,
I SHOULD BE GLAD TO
OFFER MY SERVICES
AS NEGOTIATOR
BETWEEN YOU
AND VENDIKAR.
I'VE HAD SOME
SMALL EXPERIENCES
IN SUCH MATTERS.
THERE MAY BE A CHANCE.
WE HAVE A DIRECT CHANNEL
WITH VENDIKAR'S HIGH COUNCIL.
IT HASN'T BEEN USED
IN CENTURIES.
THEN IT'S
LONG OVERDUE.
SHALL WE GO?
THERE'S A CHANCE
IT MAY WORK, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
SCOTTY?
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
CANCEL IMPLEMENTATION
OF GENERAL ORDER 24.
ALERT TRANSPORTER ROOM.
WE'RE READY TO BEAM UP.
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR ARGANA 2, NAVIGATOR.
MR. SCOTT?
SPACE DETAIL SET,
CAPTAIN.
MESSAGE FROM EMINIAR VII,
AMBASSADOR FOX REPORTS
NEGOTIATIONS UNDERWAY
WITH VENDIKAR.
OUTLOOK HOPEFUL.
GOOD.
CAPTAIN...
YOU TOOK
A BIG CHANCE.
DID I, MR. SPOCK?
THEY HAVE BEEN KILLING
3 MILLION PEOPLE A YEAR.
IT HAD BEEN GOING ON
FOR 500 YEARS.
AN ACTUAL ATTACK
WOULDN'T HAVE KILLED
ANY MORE PEOPLE
THAN ONE OF THEIR
COMPUTER ATTACKS,
BUT IT WOULD'VE
ENDED THEIR ABILITY
TO MAKE WAR.
THE FIGHTING WOULD'VE
BEEN OVER PERMANENTLY.
BUT YOU DIDN'T KNOW
THAT IT WOULD WORK.
NO...
IT WAS A CALCULATED RISK.
STILL, THE EMINIANS KEEP
A VERY ORDERLY SOCIETY,
AND ACTUAL WAR
IS A VERY MESSY BUSINESS--
A VERY, VERY MESSY BUSINESS.
I HAD A FEELING THAT THEY
WOULD DO ANYTHING TO AVOID IT,
EVEN TALK PEACE.
A FEELING IS
NOT MUCH TO GO ON.
SOMETIMES A FEELING,
MR. SPOCK,
IS ALL WE HUMANS
HAVE TO GO ON.
CAPTAIN...
YOU ALMOST MAKE ME
BELIEVE IN LUCK.
WHY, MR. SPOCK,
YOU ALMOST MAKE ME
BELIEVE IN MIRACLES.