APPROACHING
OMICRON CETI 3, SIR.
STANDARD ORBIT,
MR. PAINTER.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
YES, LIEUTENANT.
I'VE BEEN TRANSMITTING
A CONTACT SIGNAL
EVERY FIVE MINUTES
AS ORDERED, SIR.
ALL I GET IS DEAD AIR.
SHALL I CONTINUE?
MAINTAIN
TRANSMISSION PATTERN
UNTIL WE'VE
ESTABLISHED ORBIT.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK...
THERE WERE 150 MEN,
WOMEN, AND CHILDREN
IN THAT COLONY.
WHAT ARE THE
CHANCES OF SURVIVORS?
ABSOLUTELY NONE,
CAPTAIN.
BERTOLD RAYS ARE SUCH
A RECENT DISCOVERY
WE DO NOT YET HAVE
FULL KNOWLEDGE
OF THEIR NATURE.
IT IS KNOWN, HOWEVER,
THAT
LIVING ANIMAL TISSUE
DISINTEGRATES
UNDER EXPOSURE.
SANDOVAL'S GROUP
COULD NOT HAVE SURVIVED
AFTER THREE YEARS.
ARE YOU SAYING
THAT THOSE PEOPLE
BUILT A FUTURE IN
A PLACE KNOWING THEY
MIGHT NOT SURVIVE?
I AM SAYING THEY KNEW
THERE WAS A RISK.
AND WHAT ABOUT US?
CAN WE AFFORD
TO SEND PEOPLE DOWN TO
THE PLANET'S SURFACE?
THE BREAKDOWN
OF TISSUE DOES NOT
DEVELOP IMMEDIATELY.
WE CAN RISK
A LIMITED EXPOSURE.
WE'VE ESTABLISHED
ORBIT, SIR.
AND I'VE PINPOINTED
A SETTLEMENT.
THANK YOU,
MR. PAINTER.
MR. SPOCK, EQUIP
A LANDING PARTY OF FIVE
TO ACCOMPANY ME
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
INCLUDE DR. McCOY
AND A BIOLOGIST.
I'LL WANT THEM
IN 10 MINUTES.
[TRANSPORTER EFFECT WHINES]
[TRICORDER HUMS]
[KIRK]
ANOTHER DREAM THAT FAILED.
THERE'S NOTHING SADDER.
IT TOOK THESE
PEOPLE A YEAR
TO MAKE THE TRIP
FROM EARTH.
THEY CAME ALL THAT WAY...
AND DIED.
HARDLY THAT, SIR.
WELCOME TO
OMICRON CETI 3.
I'M ELIAS SANDOVAL.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE,
NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3417.3--
WE THOUGHT OUR MISSION
TO OMICRON CETI 3
WOULD BE AN UNHAPPY ONE.
WE HAD EXPECTED TO FIND
NO SURVIVORS OF
THE AGRICULTURAL
COLONY THERE.
APPARENTLY, OUR INFORMATION
WAS INCORRECT.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN
ANYONE OUTSIDE
OUR OWN GROUP
FOR FOUR YEARS,
SINCE WE LEFT
EARTH.
WE'VE BEEN
EXPECTING SOMEONE
FOR SOME TIME.
OUR SUBSPACE
RADIO DIDN'T
WORK PROPERLY.
I'M AFRAID
WE DIDN'T HAVE
ANYONE HERE
WHO COULD MASTER
ITS INTRICACIES.
ACTUALLY, MR. SANDOVAL,
WE DIDN'T COME HERE BECAUSE
OF YOUR SILENT RADIO.
IT MAKES LITTLE
DIFFERENCE, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE HERE. WE'RE
HAPPY TO SEE YOU.
COME. LET ME SHOW
YOU OUR SETTLEMENT.
PURE SPECULATION,
JUST AN EDUCATED GUESS,
I'D SAY
THAT MAN IS ALIVE.
CAPTAIN, THIS PLANET
IS BEING BOMBARDED
BY BERTOLD RAYS
AS OUR REPORTS
INDICATED.
AT THIS INTENSITY,
WE'LL BE SAFE
FOR A WEEK
IF NECESSARY.
BUT...
BUT THESE PEOPLE
SHOULDN'T BE ALIVE.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THAT THEY'RE NOT?
YOU SHOOK HANDS
WITH HIM, JIM.
HIS FLESH WAS WARM.
HE'S ALIVE.
THERE'S NO DOUBT
ABOUT THAT.
THERE'S ALSO NO
QUESTION OF THE FACT
THAT BERTOLD RAYS
ARE INCONTROVERTIBLY
DEADLY.
THERE'S NO MIRACLE
CONNECTED WITH IT,
DOCTOR.
YOU KNOW THAT.
NO CURES, NO SERUMS,
NO ANTIDOTES.
IF A MAN IS EXPOSED
LONG ENOUGH,
HE DIES.
GENTLEMEN...
WE'RE DEBATING
IN A VACUUM.
LET'S GO GET SOME ANSWERS.
THERE ARE
TWO OTHER SETTLEMENTS,
BUT WE HAVE
45 COLONISTS HERE.
WHAT WAS THE REASON
FOR THE DISPERSAL?
WELL, WE FELT THAT
THREE GROUPS
WOULD HAVE A BETTER
CHANCE FOR GROWTH.
IF DISEASE WERE
TO STRIKE ONE GROUP,
THEN THE OTHERS
WOULD BE LESS LIKELY
TO BE AFFECTED.
YOU SEE,
OMICRON IS AN IDEAL
AGRICULTURAL PLANET.
WE DETERMINED NOT
TO SUFFER THE FATE
OF EXPEDITIONS
THAT WENT BEFORE US.
ELIAS.
LAYLA,
COME MEET OUR GUESTS.
THIS IS LAYLA COLOMI,
OUR BOTANIST.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
DR. McCOY,
MR. SPOCK.
MR. SPOCK AND I
HAVE MET BEFORE.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME.
MR. SANDOVAL,
WE DO HAVE
A MISSION HERE.
EXAMINATIONS, TESTS.
BY ALL MEANS,
MAKE THEM.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
OUR SETTLEMENT
AN INTERESTING ONE.
OUR PHILOSOPHY
IS A SIMPLE ONE
THAT MEN SHOULD
RETURN TO A LESS
COMPLICATED LIFE.
WE HAVE
FEW MECHANICAL
THINGS HERE.
NO VEHICLES,
NO WEAPONS.
WE HAVE HARMONY HERE.
COMPLETE PEACE.
WE'LL TRY
NOT TO INTERFERE
WITH YOUR WORK.
MAKE YOURSELVES
AT HOME, GENTLEMEN.
WHAT EXACTLY ARE WE
LOOKING FOR ANYWAY, SIR?
WHATEVER DOESN'T
LOOK RIGHT.
WHATEVER THAT IS.
WHEN IT COMES TO FARMS,
I WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT
LOOKED RIGHT OR WRONG
IF IT WERE 2 FEET
FROM ME.
HEY.
WHAT IS IT?
NO COWS.
THIS BARN ISN'T
EVEN BUILT FOR THEM,
JUST FOR STORAGE.
COME TO
THINK OF IT,
WE HAVEN'T SEEN
ANY ANIMALS.
NO HORSES, NO PIGS,
NOT EVEN A DOG.
NOTHING.
YOU'VE KNOWN
THE VULCANIAN?
ON EARTH,
SIX YEARS AGO.
DID YOU LOVE HIM?
IF I DID,
IT WAS IMPORTANT
ONLY TO MYSELF.
HOW DID HE FEEL?
MR. SPOCK'S FEELINGS
WERE NEVER
EXPRESSED TO ME.
IT IS SAID
HE HAS NONE TO GIVE.
WOULD YOU LIKE HIM
TO STAY WITH US NOW?
TO BE AS ONE OF US?
THERE IS NO CHOICE,
ELIAS.
HE WILL STAY.
[MEDICAL TRICORDER HUMS]
THAT'LL BE ALL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ANYTHING?
I'VE EXAMINED
NINE MEN SO FAR
VARYING IN AGES
FROM 23 TO 59.
THEY'RE ALL IN
PERFECT CONDITION.
TEXTBOOK RESPONSES.
HEART/LUNGS, EXCELLENT.
COORDINATION,
EXCELLENT.
REFLEXES, EXCELLENT.
IF THERE ARE MANY
MORE OF THEM,
I CAN THROW
AWAY MY SHINGLE.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
A TOTAL ABSENCE OF
LIFE ON THE PLANET
WITH THE EXCEPTION
OF THE COLONISTS
THEMSELVES
AND VARIOUS TYPES
OF FLORA.
SULU HAD THE SAME
OBSERVATION.
ANY EXPLANATIONS?
NOT AT THE MOMENT,
SIR.
I AM CONDUCTING
VARIOUS TESTS
WITH THE TRICORDER,
BUT RESULTS
ARE INCONCLUSIVE.
VERY WELL. CONTINUE
INVESTIGATIONS.
KIRK OUT.
HMM. NO ANIMALS?
THAT'S PECULIAR.
YES, ESPECIALLY
IN VIEW OF THE FACT
THAT THE RECORDS OF THIS
EXPEDITION INDICATE
THAT THEY DID HAVE
SOME FOR BREEDING
AND FOOD PURPOSES.
APPARENTLY,
NONE OF THEM SURVIVED.
I'D LIKE TO SEE
THE MEDICAL
RECORDS
ON THE
EXPEDITION.
YES, I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT.
OH, CAPTAIN, I'VE
BEEN LOOKING FOR YOU.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN
OUR FIELDS AND CROPS.
I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU
AND THE DOCTOR WHAT
WE'VE ACCOMPLISHED HERE.
OH, I'M AFRAID
I'LL HAVE
TO BOW OUT.
I HAVE TO CONTINUE
WITH THESE MEDICAL
EXAMINATIONS.
HOWEVER, IF I
FIND EVERYONE
ELSE'S HEALTH
TO BE AS PERFECT
AS YOURS, I...
HE PROMISED TO THROW
AWAY HIS SHINGLE.
YOU'LL FIND
NO WEAKLINGS HERE.
CAPTAIN.
THIS IS THE REASON,
THIS SOIL WILL GROW
ANYTHING WE PLANT
IN IT.
IT'S A PERFECT
WORLD.
WE HAVE
A MODERATE CLIMATE,
MODERATE RAINS
ALL YEAR ROUND.
IT GIVES US
ALL WE NEED.
IT IS PERFECT.
PARDON ME, CAPTAIN.
BIOLOGY REPORT READY, SIR.
I HAVE WORK TO ATTEND
TO MYSELF, CAPTAIN.
GO AHEAD,
LIEUTENANT.
I HEARD SANDOVAL
SAYING THEY COULD
GROW ANYTHING HERE.
THAT'S TRUE, SIR.
THEY'VE GOT A VARIETY
OF CROPS IN.
GRAINS, POTATOES, BEANS.
MAKE YOUR POINT.
WELL, SIR, FOR AN
AGRICULTURAL COLONY,
THEY ACTUALLY HAVE VERY
LITTLE ACREAGE PLANTED.
THERE'S ENOUGH
TO SUSTAIN THE COLONY,
BUT VERY LITTLE MORE.
IT'S LIKE A JIGSAW
PUZZLE ALL ONE COLOR.
NO KEY TO WHERE
THE PIECES FIT IN.
WHY?
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
THIS IS McCOY, JIM.
I THINK YOU'D BETTER
GET BACK HERE.
TROUBLE?
NO, BUT I'D LIKE YOU TO
SEE THIS FOR YOURSELF.
ON MY WAY.
SANDOVAL'S MEDICAL
RECORD FOUR YEARS AGO
WHEN THE EXPEDITION
LEFT EARTH.
HE REGISTERED
SCAR TISSUE ON HIS LUNGS
FROM LOBAR PNEUMONIA
SUFFERED WHEN
HE WAS A CHILD.
NO MAJOR OPERATIONS,
BUT THERE WAS
AN APPENDECTOMY.
RECEIVED ALL REQUIRED
INOCULATIONS, ET CETERA.
WHAT'S SO STRANGE
ABOUT THAT?
NOTHING.
BUT I EXAMINED THAT MAN
NOT MORE THAN TWO HOURS AGO,
AND DO YOU KNOW WHAT
HIS READINGS WERE?
PERFECT, PERFECT,
AND PERFECT.
JUST LIKE EVERYONE ELSE
I'VE EXAMINED HERE.
INSTRUMENT MALFUNCTION?
NO. I THOUGHT OF THAT,
AND I TESTED IT ON MYSELF.
IT ACCURATELY RECORDED
MY LACK OF TONSILS
AND THOSE TWO BROKEN
RIBS I HAD ONCE.
IT DID NOT RECORD THE SCAR
TISSUE ON SANDOVAL'S LUNGS,
BUT IT DID RECORD
A HEALTHY APPENDIX
WHERE ONE WAS
SUPPOSEDLY REMOVED.
[TRICORDER HUMS]
NOTHING.
NOT EVEN INSECTS.
YET YOUR PLANTS GROW,
AND YOU'VE
SURVIVED EXPOSURE
TO BERTOLD RAYS.
THAT CAN BE EXPLAINED.
PLEASE DO.
LATER.
I HAVE NEVER UNDERSTOOD
THE FEMALE CAPACITY
TO AVOID A DIRECT
ANSWER TO ANY QUESTION.
AND I NEVER
UNDERSTOOD YOU.
UNTIL NOW.
THERE WAS ALWAYS
A PLACE IN HERE
WHERE NO ONE COULD COME.
THERE WAS ONLY THE FACE
YOU ALLOW PEOPLE TO SEE.
ONLY ONE SIDE
YOU'D ALLOW THEM TO KNOW.
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
HOW YOUR PEOPLE HAVE
MANAGED TO SURVIVE HERE.
I MISSED YOU.
LOGICALLY,
YOU SHOULD ALL BE DEAD.
IF I TELL YOU
HOW WE SURVIVE,
WILL YOU TRY
TO UNDERSTAND
HOW WE FEEL ABOUT
OUR LIFE HERE?
ABOUT EACH OTHER?
EMOTIONS
ARE ALIEN TO ME.
I'M A SCIENTIST.
SOMEONE ELSE
MIGHT BELIEVE THAT--
YOUR SHIPMATES,
YOUR CAPTAIN--
BUT NOT ME.
COME.
MR. SANDOVAL,
WITHIN THE HOUR,
I'VE RECEIVED ORDERS
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND
TO EVACUATE ALL PERSONNEL
FROM THIS COLONY.
NATURALLY,
YOU'LL INFORM YOUR PEOPLE
TO BEGIN PREPARATIONS.
WE WILL HAVE
ACCOMMODATIONS FOR YOU
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE.
NO.
UH, IT'S NOT AN ARBITRARY
DECISION ON MY PART, SIR.
I HAVE MY ORDERS.
CAPTAIN, IT'S ENTIRELY
UNNECESSARY.
WE'RE IN NO DANGER HERE.
WE'VE EXPLAINED
THE BERTOLD RAYS
TO YOU
AND
THEIR EFFECT.
CAN'T YOU
UNDERSTAND?
DOCTOR, HOW CAN
I MAKE YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOUR OWN INSTRUMENTS
HAVE SHOWN THAT WE'RE
ALL IN PERFECT HEALTH.
WE'VE HAD NO DEATHS HERE.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR ANIMALS?
WE'RE VEGETARIANS.
THAT DOESN'T ANSWER
MY QUESTION, SIR.
WHY DID ALL
YOUR ANIMALS DIE?
CAPTAIN, YOU STRESS
VERY UNIMPORTANT MATTERS.
WE WILL NOT LEAVE.
IT'S NOT MUCH FURTHER.
YOU'VE NOT YET
EXPLAINED THE NATURE
OF THIS THING.
ITS BASIC PROPERTIES
AND ELEMENTS ARE
NOT IMPORTANT.
WHAT IS IMPORTANT
IS IT GIVES LIFE,
PEACE, LOVE.
WHAT YOU'RE DESCRIBING
WAS ONCE KNOWN
IN THE VERNACULAR
AS A HAPPINESS PILL.
AND YOU,
AS A SCIENTIST,
SHOULD KNOW THAT
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
COME.
I WAS ONE OF
THE FIRST TO FIND THEM.
THE SPORES.
SPORES?
NO...
IT SHOULDN'T HURT.
NO, I CAN'T.
PLEASE, DON'T!
NOT LIKE THIS,
IT DIDN'T HURT US.
I AM NOT LIKE YOU.
NOW...
NOW YOU BELONG
TO ALL OF US...
AND WE TO YOU.
THERE'S NO NEED TO HIDE
YOUR INNER FACE ANY LONGER.
WE UNDERSTAND.
I LOVE YOU.
I CAN LOVE YOU.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL--
WE HAVE BEEN ORDERED
BY STARFLEET COMMAND
TO EVACUATE THE COLONY
ON OMICRON 3.
HOWEVER, THE COLONY LEADER,
ELIAS SANDOVAL,
HAS REFUSED
ALL COOPERATION
AND WILL NOT LISTEN
TO ANY ARGUMENTS.
SANDOVAL.
CAPTAIN,
YOUR ARGUMENTS
ARE VERY VALID,
BUT THEY DO NOT
APPLY TO US.
YOU'RE BEING
UNREASONABLE.
NEVERTHELESS,
EXCUSE ME.
MY ORDERS ARE TO REMOVE
ALL THE COLONISTS,
AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
I INTEND TO DO
WITH OR WITHOUT
YOUR HELP.
WITHOUT,
I SHOULD THINK.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO USE A BUTTERFLY
NET ON HIM, JIM?
NO, I DON'T THINK--
CAPTAIN!
WE'VE CHECKED OUT
EVERYTHING.
IT ALL SEEMS NORMAL
EXCEPT FOR THE ABSENCE
OF ANY ANIMALS.
WE HAVE ORDERS
TO EVACUATE ALL COLONISTS
TO STARBASE 27.
I WANT LANDING PARTIES TO
COORDINATE THE COLONISTS
AND PREPARE THEM TO
TRANSPORT UP TO THE SHIP.
WE'LL NEED EXTRA
ACCOMMODATIONS ABOARD.
WHERE'S MR. SPOCK
AND MR. DeSALLE?
WE HAVEN'T SEEN THEM SINCE
WE BEGAN OUR CHECK.
DeSALLE SAID HE WAS
GOING TO EXAMINE
SOME NATIVE PLANTS
HE FOUND.
DID SPOCK
CALL IN AT ALL?
NO, HE DIDN'T.
SPOCK?
SEE TO THE LANDING
PARTIES, WILL YOU,
MR. SULU?
YES, SIR.
SPOCK?
[BEEP BEEP]
THAT ONE LOOKS
LIKE A DRAGON.
YOU SEE THE TAIL
AND THE DORSAL SPINES?
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A DRAGON.
[BEEP BEEP]
I HAVE.
ON BARENGARIUS 7.
BUT I'VE NEVER STOPPED
TO LOOK AT CLOUDS BEFORE.
[BEEP BEEP BEEP]
OR RAINBOWS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN
TELL YOU EXACTLY WHY
ONE APPEARS IN THE SKY,
BUT CONSIDERING ITS BEAUTY
HAS ALWAYS BEEN
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
NOT HERE.
[BEEP BEEP]
SPOCK!
YES.
WHAT DID YOU WANT?
SPOCK,
IS THAT YOU?
YES, CAPTAIN.
WHAT DID YOU WANT?
WHERE ARE YOU?
I DON'T BELIEVE
I WANT TO TELL YOU.
SPOCK, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING,
BUT THIS IS AN ORDER.
REPORT BACK TO ME
AT THE SETTLEMENT
IN 10 MINUTES.
WE'RE EVACUATING
ALL COLONISTS
TO STARBASE 27.
NO, I DON'T
THINK SO.
YOU DON'T
THINK SO, WHAT?
I DON'T
THINK SO, SIR.
SPOCK...
REPORT TO ME
IMMEDIATELY.
SPOCK?
ACKNOWLEDGE.
SPOCK.
THE FREQUENCY IS OPEN,
BUT HE DOESN'T ANSWER.
THAT DIDN'T SOUND
AT ALL LIKE SPOCK, JIM.
NO, IT--
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
YOU MIGHT LIKE HIM
IF HE MELLOWED A LITTLE.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT!
YOU SAID THAT.
NOT EXACTLY.
HE MIGHT BE IN TROUBLE.
YES. TAKE OVER
THE LANDING PARTY DETAIL.
START GETTING THOSE
COLONISTS ABOARD.
HOW WILL YOU
FIND SPOCK?
THE FREQUENCY IS OPEN.
IT'LL ACT
AS A HOMING DEVICE.
CONTACT DeSALLE.
HAVE HIM MEET YOU HERE.
MAKE SURE
THE LANDING PARTY
WORKS IN TEAMS OF TWO.
I DON'T WANT ANYBODY
LEFT ALONE DOWN HERE.
[COMMUNICATOR WHINES]
HA HA HA HA!
SPOCK.
AHEM!
MR. SPOCK?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THOSE THINGS,
DeSALLE?
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A CLOSE LOOK
AT THESE, DOC.
THEY'RE VERY
INTERESTING.
MR. SPOCK.
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR MIND?
YOU WERE TOLD TO
REPORT TO ME AT ONCE.
I DIDN'T WANT TO, JIM.
YOU--
YES, I CAN SEE THAT.
MISS COLOMI, YOU'LL
HAVE TO COME BACK
WITH US TO
THE SETTLEMENT
AND PREPARE
TO TRANSPORT
UP TO THE SHIP.
THERE'LL BE
NO EVACUATION, JIM.
BUT PERHAPS WE SHOULD
GO BACK AND GET YOU
STRAIGHTENED OUT.
MR. SULU, MR. SPOCK
IS UNDER ARREST,
AND HE'S
IN YOUR CUSTODY
UNTIL WE GET BACK
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
VERY WELL.
COME WITH ME.
WHAT'S...
MR. SULU UNDERSTANDS,
DON'T YOU, MR. SULU?
YES.
I SEE NOW.
OF COURSE WE CAN'T
REMOVE THE COLONY.
IT'D BE WRONG.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THESE PLANTS ARE
OR HOW THEY WORK,
BUT YOU'RE ALL GOING BACK
TO THE SETTLEMENT WITH ME,
AND THOSE COLONISTS
ARE GOING ABOARD THE SHIP.
I CAN SEE THE CAPTAIN IS
GOING TO BE DIFFICULT.
READY TO BEAM UP.
HIYA, JIMMY BOY!
HEY, I'VE TAKEN CARE
OF EVERYTHING.
ALL Y'ALL GOTTA
DO IS JUST
RELAX.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS!
HOW MANY OF THOSE
DID YOU BEAM UP?
OH, MUST BE
MIGHT NIGH ONTO
100 BY NOW.
HEY, DOC, I'M READY
TO ENERGIZE.
EVERYTHING O.K.
WITH THOSE PLANTS?
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
BEAM ME UP.
WELL, SURE,
IF YOU WANT.
I MOST CERTAINLY DO.
ENERGIZE.
LIEUTENANT...
PUT ME THROUGH
TO ADMIRAL KOMAK
AT STARFLEET.
OH, I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU CAN'T DO THAT?
FOLLOW
STANDARD PROCEDURE.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
OH, I KNOW IT IS,
CAPTAIN.
BUT, YOU SEE,
ALL COMMUNICATIONS ARE OUT.
OUT?
I SHORT-CIRCUITED
THEM, EXCEPT FOR
SHIP-TO-SURFACE.
WE'LL NEED THAT
FOR A WHILE.
IT'S REALLY
FOR THE BEST,
CAPTAIN.
GO BACK TO YOUR STATIONS.
GET BACK
TO YOUR STATIONS.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
WE'RE ALL
TRANSPORTING DOWN
TO JOIN THE COLONY.
I SAID GET BACK
TO YOUR STATION.
NO, SIR.
THIS IS MUTINY, MISTER.
YES, SIR. IT IS.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3417.5.
THE POD PLANTS
HAVE SPREAD SPORES
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP
CARRIED BY
THE VENTILATION SYSTEM.
UNDER THEIR INFLUENCE,
MY CREW IS DESERTING
TO JOIN THE OMICRON COLONY,
AND I CAN'T STOP THEM.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I HAVE NOT BEEN INFECTED,
NOR CAN I GET DR. McCOY
TO EXPLAIN
THE PHYSICAL,
PSYCHOLOGICAL ASPECTS
OF THE INFECTION.
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN ANY PHYSICAL,
PSYCHOLOGICAL ASPECTS,
JIM-BOY.
WE'RE ALL PERFECTLY
HEALTHY DOWN HERE.
I'VE HEARD THAT WORD
A LOT LATELY.
PERFECT.
EVERYTHING'S
YEAH. THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S JUST WHAT IT IS.
I'LL BET YOU'VE
EVEN GROWN YOUR
TONSILS BACK.
SHO'NUF.
HEY, JIM-BOY,
Y'ALL EVER HAVE
A REAL COLD GEORGIA-STYLE
MINT JULEP, HUH?
LOOK, BONES,
I NEED YOUR HELP.
CAN YOU RUN TESTS,
BLOOD SAMPLES,
ANYTHING TO GIVE US
A LEAD ON WHAT
THESE THINGS ARE,
HOW TO
COUNTERACT THEM?
WHO WANTS TO COUNTERACT
PARADISE, JIM-BOY?
McCOY OUT.
BONES.
ALMOST THE ENTIRE
SHIP'S COMPLEMENT
HAS BEAMED DOWN.
I'M VERY PLEASED.
THE ENTIRE LANDING
OPERATION IS PROCEEDING
QUITE WELL.
WHERE'S McCOY?
HE WENT OFF
TO CREATE SOMETHING
CALLED A MINT JULEP.
THAT'S A DRINK, JIM.
CAPTAIN, WHY
DON'T YOU JOIN US?
IN YOUR OWN
PRIVATE PARADISE.
THE SPORES HAVE
MADE IT THAT.
WHERE DID THEY ORIGINATE?
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY.
THEY DRIFTED THROUGH SPACE
UNTIL THEY FINALLY
LANDED HERE.
YOU SEE, THEY ACTUALLY
THRIVE ON BERTOLD RAYS.
THE PLANTS ACT
AS A REPOSITORY
FOR THOUSANDS
OF MICROSCOPIC SPORES
UNTIL THEY FIND
A HUMAN BODY TO INHABIT.
IN RETURN,
THEY GIVE YOU
COMPLETE HEALTH
AND PEACE OF MIND.
THAT'S PARADISE?
WE HAVE NO NEED
OR WANT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S A TRUE EDEN, JIM.
THERE IS BELONGING...
AND LOVE.
NO WANTS. NO NEEDS.
WE WEREN'T MEANT
FOR THAT. NONE OF US.
MAN STAGNATES
IF HE HAS NO AMBITION,
NO DESIRE TO BE
MORE THAN HE IS.
WE HAVE WHAT WE NEED.
EXCEPT A CHALLENGE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND, JIM,
BUT YOU'LL COME AROUND...
SOONER OR LATER.
JOIN US.
PLEASE.
I'M GOING BACK
TO THE SHIP.
ENGINEERING? SCOTTY?
BIOCHEMISTRY LAB?
SECURITY?
IS THERE ANYONE
ON BOARD?
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3417.7.
EXCEPT FOR MYSELF,
ALL CREW PERSONNEL
HAVE TRANSPORTED
TO THE SURFACE
OF THE PLANET.
MUTINIED.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
HAS EFFECTIVELY SABOTAGED
THE COMMUNICATIONS
STATION.
I CAN ONLY CONTACT
THE SURFACE OF THE PLANET.
THE SHIP...
CAN BE MAINTAINED
IN ORBIT FOR SEVERAL MONTHS,
BUT EVEN WITH
AUTOMATIC CONTROLS,
I CANNOT PILOT HER ALONE.
IN EFFECT,
I AM MAROONED HERE.
I'M BEGINNING
TO REALIZE...
JUST HOW BIG THIS SHIP
REALLY IS, HOW QUIET.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO GET MY CREW BACK,
HOW TO COUNTERACT
THE EFFECT OF THE SPORES.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I CAN OFFER
AGAINST...
PARADISE.
ENTERPRISE
TO MR. SPOCK.
YES, JIM.
WHAT IS IT NOW?
I'VE JOINED YOU.
I UNDERSTAND NOW.
WONDERFUL, JIM.
WHEN WILL YOU
BEAM DOWN?
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
IN MY QUARTERS
I WANT TO PACK.
GOOD. LAYLA AND I
WILL MEET YOU AT
THE BEAMDOWN POINT.
KIRK OUT.
NO.
NO!
I...
CAN'T...
LEAVE!
EMOTIONS.
VIOLENT EMOTIONS.
NEEDS.
ANGER.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--SUPPLEMENTAL.
I THINK I'VE
DISCOVERED THE ANSWER...
BUT TO CARRY OUT MY PLAN
ENTAILS CONSIDERABLE RISK.
MR. SPOCK IS
MUCH STRONGER THAN
THE ORDINARY HUMAN BEING.
AROUSED, HIS GREAT
PHYSICAL STRENGTH
COULD KILL.
BUT IT'S A RISK
I'LL HAVE TO TAKE.
ENTERPRISE TO MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
IT'S JIM.
WHAT'S KEEPING
YOU, JIM?
WE'VE BEEN WAITING.
I'VE BEEN PACKING
SOME THINGS,
AND I REALIZE THERE'S
SOME EQUIPMENT HERE
THAT WE SHOULD HAVE
DOWN AT THE SETTLEMENT.
YOU KNOW WE CAN'T
COME BACK ON BOARD
ONCE THE LAST
OF US HAS LEFT.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO BEAM UP A PARTY?
NO. I THINK
YOU AND I CAN HANDLE IT.
WHY DON'T YOU
BEAM UP NOW?
JUST A MOMENT.
IT WON'T TAKE LONG.
DO YOU MIND?
I'LL WAIT.
READY TO BEAM UP, JIM.
ENERGIZING.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU MUTINOUS, DISLOYAL,
COMPUTERIZED HALF-BREED,
WE'LL SEE ABOUT YOU
DESERTING MY SHIP.
THE TERM HALF-BREED
IS SOMEWHAT APPLICABLE,
BUT COMPUTERIZED
IS INACCURATE.
A MACHINE CAN BE
COMPUTERIZED, NOT A MAN.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
YOU'RE A MAN?
YOU'RE AN OVERGROWN
JACK RABBIT,
AN ELF WITH
A HYPERACTIVE THYROID.
JIM,
I DON'T UNDERSTAND--
OF COURSE
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE BRAINS
TO UNDERSTAND.
ALL YOU HAVE
IS PRINTED CIRCUITS.
CAPTAIN, IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME--
WHAT CAN YOU EXPECT
FROM A SIMPERING,
DEVIL-EARED FREAK
WHOSE FATHER WAS
A COMPUTER AND
HIS MOTHER AN ENCYCLOPEDIA?
MY MOTHER WAS A TEACHER.
MY FATHER,
AN AMBASSADOR.
YOUR FATHER WAS
A COMPUTER LIKE HIS SON.
AN AMBASSADOR FROM
A PLANET OF TRAITORS.
THE VULCAN NEVER LIVED
WHO HAD AN OUNCE
OF INTEGRITY.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE DON'T--
YOU'RE A TRAITOR
FROM A RACE OF TRAITORS.
DISLOYAL TO THE CORE,
ROTTEN LIKE THE REST
OF YOUR SUBHUMAN RACE,
AND YOU'VE GOT THE GALL
TO MAKE LOVE TO THAT GIRL.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
DOES SHE KNOW
WHAT SHE'S GETTING, SPOCK?
A CARCASS FULL
OF MEMORY BANKS
WHO SHOULD BE
SQUATTING IN A MUSHROOM
INSTEAD OF
PASSING HIMSELF
OFF AS A MAN?
YOU BELONG
IN A CIRCUS, SPOCK,
NOT A STARSHIP...
RIGHT NEXT
TO THE DOG-FACED BOY.
HAD ENOUGH?
I DIDN'T REALIZE
WHAT IT TOOK
TO GET UNDER
THAT THICK HIDE OF YOURS.
ANYHOW, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SO MAD ABOUT.
IT ISN'T EVERY
FIRST OFFICER
WHO GETS TO BELT
HIS CAPTAIN...
SEVERAL TIMES.
YOU DID THAT TO ME
DELIBERATELY.
BELIEVE ME, MR. SPOCK,
IT WAS PAINFUL...
IN MORE WAYS THAN ONE.
THE SPORES.
THEY'RE GONE.
I DON'T BELONG
ANYMORE.
YOU SAID THEY WERE
BENEVOLENT AND PEACEFUL.
VIOLENT EMOTIONS
OVERWHELM THEM,
DESTROY THEM.
I HAD TO MAKE YOU
ANGRY ENOUGH
TO SHAKE OFF
THEIR INFLUENCE.
THAT'S THE ANSWER,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT MAY BE CORRECT,
CAPTAIN,
BUT TRYING
TO INITIATE A BRAWL
WITH OVER 500 CREWMEN
AND COLONISTS IS
HARDLY LOGICAL.
I HAD SOMETHING ELSE
IN MIND.
CAN YOU PUT TOGETHER
A SUBSONIC TRANSMITTER--
SOMETHING WE CAN HOOK INTO
THE COMMUNICATIONS STATION
AND BROADCAST OVER
THE COMMUNICATOR?
IT CAN BE DONE.
GOOD.
LET'S GET TO WORK.
CAPTAIN.
STRIKING
A FELLOW OFFICER
IS A COURT-MARTIAL
OFFENSE.
WELL, IF WE'RE BOTH
IN THE BRIG,
WHO'S GOING TO BUILD
THE SUBSONIC TRANSMITTER?
THAT IS QUITE
LOGICAL, CAPTAIN.
WELL, NOW, IT'S
A LITTLE EARLY
TO BE COUNTING STARS,
MISS LAYLA.
I'M WAITING
FOR MR. SPOCK
AND THE CAPTAIN
TO TRANSPORT DOWN.
THEY HAD SOME
EQUIPMENT TO BE MOVED.
BUT IT'S BEEN SO LONG.
I WISH HE'D COME BACK.
WELL, NOW, I THINK
I CAN FIX THAT FOR YOU.
ENTERPRISE?
[BEEP BEEP]
ENTERPRISE. SPOCK HERE.
THIS IS LAYLA.
I BORROWED
THE DOCTOR'S COMMUNICATOR.
I WAS WORRIED SOMETHING
MIGHT HAVE HAPPENED TO YOU.
YOU ARE ALL RIGHT,
AREN'T YOU?
YES.
YES. I'M...I'M QUITE WELL.
CAN I COME ABOARD?
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A STARSHIP BEFORE,
AND I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
ARE YOU STILL
AT THE BEAMDOWN POINT,
AND IS THE DOCTOR THERE?
YES TO BOTH QUESTIONS.
GIVE YOUR COMMUNICATOR
BACK TO DR. McCOY.
YOU WON'T NEED IT
TO BEAM UP.
IT'LL TAKE A FEW MOMENTS.
JUST WAIT THERE.
OUT.
MR. SPOCK...
MISS COLOMI IS STRICTLY
YOUR CONCERN, BUT...
SHOULD YOU TALK TO HER
WHILE SHE'S STILL
UNDER THE INFLUENCE
OF THE SPORES?
I'LL BE BACK
SHORTLY, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE NO LONGER
WITH US, ARE YOU?
I FELT SOMETHING
WAS WRONG.
IT WAS NECESSARY.
COME BACK TO
THE PLANET WITH ME.
YOU CAN BELONG AGAIN.
OH, COME BACK
WITH ME, PLEASE.
I CAN'T.
I LOVE YOU.
I SAID THAT
SIX YEARS AGO,
AND I CAN'T SEEM TO STOP
REPEATING MYSELF.
ON EARTH, YOU COULDN'T
GIVE ANYTHING OF YOURSELF.
YOU COULDN'T EVEN
PUT YOUR ARMS AROUND ME.
WE COULDN'T HAVE
ANYTHING TOGETHER THERE.
ANYTHING TOGETHER
ANYPLACE ELSE.
BUT WE'RE HAPPY HERE.
I CAN'T LOSE YOU NOW,
MR. SPOCK. I CAN'T.
I HAVE
A RESPONSIBILITY...
TO THIS SHIP...
TO THAT MAN
ON THE BRIDGE.
I AM WHAT I AM, LAYLA...
AND IF THERE ARE
SELF-MADE PURGATORIES,
THEN WE ALL HAVE
TO LIVE IN THEM.
MINE CAN BE NO WORSE
THAN SOMEONE ELSE'S.
I HAVE LOST YOU,
HAVEN'T I?
NOT ONLY YOU,
I'VE LOST ALL OF IT.
THE SPORES...
I'VE LOST THEM, TOO.
THE CAPTAIN DISCOVERED
THAT STRONG EMOTIONS
AND NEEDS
DESTROY THE SPORE
INFLUENCE.
AND THIS IS FOR MY GOOD?
DO YOU MIND IF I SAY
I STILL LOVE YOU?
YOU NEVER TOLD ME
IF YOU HAD ANOTHER
NAME, MR. SPOCK.
YOU COULDN'T
PRONOUNCE IT.
THEY'LL NOT HEAR THIS,
OF COURSE.
IT'LL BE MORE
A SENSATION OF FEELING IT.
AS THOUGH SOMEBODY
HAD PUT ITCHING
POWDER
ON THEIR SKIN.
PRECISELY.
IT SHOULD BEGIN
TO WORK ON THEIR NERVES
IN A FEW MINUTES.
[HIGH-PITCHED HUM]
SORRY, DeSALLE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
I SAID I WAS SORRY.
MORE LIKE YOU'RE CLUMSY.
IF YOU HADN'T
GOTTEN IN MY WAY...
OOH!
COME ON. BREAK IT UP.
BREAK IT UP.
WELL, DOCTOR,
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT WHAT SORT OF WORK
I COULD ASSIGN YOU TO.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
WHAT SORT OF WORK?
I'M A DOCTOR.
NOT ANYMORE, OF COURSE.
WE DON'T NEED YOU...
NOT AS A DOCTOR.
OH, NO?
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE
JUST HOW FAST I CAN PUT
YOU IN A HOSPITAL?
I AM THE LEADER
OF THIS COLONY.
I'LL ASSIGN YOU
TO WHATEVER WORK
I THINK IS SUITABLE.
JUST A MINUTE.
YOU'D BETTER MAKE ME
A MECHANIC.
THEN I CAN TREAT
LITTLE TIN GODS LIKE YOU.
SORRY, SANDOVAL.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT MADE ME DO THAT.
WE'VE DONE
NOTHING HERE.
NO ACCOMPLISHMENTS,
NO PROGRESS.
THREE YEARS WASTED.
WE WANTED TO MAKE
THIS PLANET A GARDEN.
YOU CAN'T STAY HERE.
YOU CAN'T SURVIVE
WITHOUT THE SPORES.
AFTER YOU'VE CLEARED
AT THE STARBASE,
YOU COULD BE RELOCATED.
IT DEPENDS UPON
WHAT YOU WANT.
I THINK I'D...
I THINK WE'D LIKE TO
GET SOME WORK DONE.
THE WORK WE STARTED
OUT TO DO.
ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE.
THIS IS McCOY. SANDOVAL
WOULD LIKE TO TALK
TO THE CAPTAIN.
JUST A MOMENT.
THEY'RE ALL BEGINNING
TO CALL IN, CAPTAIN.
RATHER CONTRITELY,
I SHOULD SAY.
SANDOVAL WISHES
TO SPEAK TO YOU.
PUT HIM ON THE SPEAKER.
KIRK HERE.
OH, CAPTAIN, AS
I UNDERSTOOD IT,
YOU WERE TO
TRANSPORT US
TO STARBASE 27.
WE'LL GIVE YOU
EVERY COOPERATION.
START MAKING
PREPARATIONS,
MR. SANDOVAL.
WE'LL BEGIN TRANSPORTING
YOUR PEOPLE ABOARD
AS SOON AS MORE
OF OUR CREW CHECKS IN.
WELL, JIM,
I'VE JUST EXAMINED
THE LAST
OF THE COLONISTS,
AND THEY'RE ALL
IN ABSOLUTELY PERFECT,
PERFECT HEALTH.
A FRINGE BENEFIT
LEFT OVER BY THE SPORES.
GOOD.
WELL, THAT'S
THE SECOND TIME
MAN'S BEEN THROWN
OUT OF PARADISE.
NO, NO, BONES.
THIS TIME WE WALKED
OUT ON OUR OWN.
MAYBE WE WEREN'T
MEANT FOR PARADISE.
MAYBE WE WERE MEANT
TO FIGHT OUR WAY THROUGH--
STRUGGLE,
CLAW OUR WAY UP,
SCRATCH FOR EVERY INCH
OF THE WAY.
MAYBE WE CAN'T STROLL
TO THE MUSIC OF THE LUTE.
WE MUST MARCH
TO THE SOUND OF DRUMS.
POETRY, CAPTAIN.
NONREGULATION.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD
MUCH FROM YOU
ABOUT OMICRON CETI 3,
MR. SPOCK.
I HAVE LITTLE TO SAY
ABOUT IT, CAPTAIN,
EXCEPT THAT FOR
THE FIRST TIME
IN MY LIFE...
I WAS HAPPY.