WHO'S THERE?
IT'S YOUR RELIEF, SAM.
ALL QUIET?
DIDN'T SEE
A THING, CHIEF.
NOBODY EVER DOES.
WHATEVER THE THING IS,
IT'S ALREADY KILLED
50 PEOPLE.
I NEVER REALIZED BEFORE
HOW DARK IT IS DOWN HERE.
STAY ON YOUR TOES,
SCHMITTER.
KEEP YOUR PHASER
IN YOUR HAND
AT ALL TIMES.
WHAT GOOD WILL THAT DO?
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED
TO ED APPEL
WHEN HE TOOK A SHOT
AT THE THING.
HOW ABOUT ALL THOSE
OTHER PEOPLE,
BEFORE THE MONSTER
GOT THEM?
I'M SORRY, SCHMITTER,
I KNOW HOW YOU FEEL,
BUT WE'VE GOT
TO HAVE GUARDS.
OK, CHIEF.
I'LL DO WHAT I CAN.
KEEP ALERT.
IF YOU HEAR ANYTHING OR
SEE ANYTHING, CALL IN.
SOMEBODY CAN BE HERE
IN 3 MINUTES.
A LOT CAN HAPPEN
CHIEF, IS IT TRUE
THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS ON ITS WAY?
IT'S COMING.
YOU THINK IT COULD GET HERE
IN THE NEXT 4 HOURS?
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
[FIERY NOISE]
NO.
AAH!
COME ON.
AAH...
SCHMITTER.
LIKE THE REST OF THEM.
BURNED TO A CRISP.
Kirk: SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3196.1.
A DISTRESS CALL
FROM THE PERGIUM
PRODUCTION STATION ON JANUS 6
HAS BROUGHT THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO THAT
LONG-ESTABLISHED COLONY.
MR. SPOCK, DR. McCOY,
AND I HAVE BEAMED DOWN
TO MEET WITH
CHIEF ENGINEER VANDERBERG,
ADMINISTRATIVE HEAD
OF JANUS 6.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S ASSUME
THERE IS A MONSTER.
WHAT HAS IT DONE?
WHEN DID IT START?
ABOUT 3 MONTHS AGO,
WE OPENED UP A NEW LEVEL.
SENSORS GAVE US
AN UNUSUALLY RICH
PERGIUM READING.
NOT ONLY PERGIUM,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
URANIUM, SERIUM, PLATINUM.
THE WHOLE PLANET'S
LIKE THAT.
IT'S A TREASURE HOUSE.
YES, WE'RE AWARE
OF THAT.
IF MINING CONDITIONS
WEREN'T SO DIFFICULT,
JANUS 6 COULD SUPPLY
THE MINERAL NEEDS
OF A THOUSAND PLANETS.
BUT WHAT HAPPENED?
FIRST, THE AUTOMATIC
MACHINERY, PIECE BY PIECE,
STARTED TO ALMOST
DISINTEGRATE.
METAL BEGAN
DISSOLVING AWAY.
THERE WAS NO REASON
FOR IT,
AND OUR CHEMISTS
WERE UNABLE TO ANALYZE
THE CORROSIVE AGENT.
I'M SURE THERE
IS AN ANSWER.
IT SIMPLY HAS NOT
YET BEEN DISCOVERED.
YES, IT HAS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS
BUTCHERING MONSTER IS,
BUT I KNOW
WHAT IT'S DOING.
OUR MAINTENANCE
ENGINEER SENT DOWN
TO THE DRIFTS
TO REPAIR
THE CORRODED MACHINERY.
WE FOUND THEM...
SEARED TO A CRISP.
VOLCANIC ACTIVITY?
THERE IS NO CURRENT
VOLCANIC ACTIVITY
ON THIS PLANET, CAPTAIN.
HE'S RIGHT. NONE.
AT FIRST, THE DEATHS
WERE DOWN DEEP,
BUT THEY'VE BEEN
MOVING UP TOWARD
OUR LEVELS.
THE LAST MAN
DIED TWO DAYS AGO
3 LEVELS BELOW THIS.
SAME WAY? BURNED?
I'D LIKE
TO EXAMINE THE BODY.
WE KEPT IT FOR YOU.
THERE ISN'T MUCH LEFT.
ROBERTS WILL SHOW YOU.
IT ISN'T PRETTY.
YOU POST
SENTRIES? GUARDS?
OF COURSE. 5 OF THEM
HAVE DIED.
WHO ELSE HAS SEEN THIS?
I HAVE.
THIS IS ED APPEL,
CHIEF PROCESSING
ENGINEER.
DESCRIBE IT.
I CAN'T.
I ONLY GOT
A GLIMPSE OF IT,
BUT IT'S...
BIG AND SHAGGY.
ED SHOT IT.
OH. YOU MEAN
SHOT AT IT.
NO. I MEAN SHOT IT.
WITH THIS.
FASCINATING.
A GOOD, CLEAN SHOT.
DIDN'T EVEN
SLOW IT DOWN.
WELL, I'VE MADE
MY REPORT TO YOU.
PRODUCTION'S STOPPED,
NOBODY WILL GO INTO
THE LOWER LEVELS,
AND I DON'T BLAME THEM.
IF THE FEDERATION
WANTS PERGIUM,
THEN YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE,
MR. VANDERBERG.
YOU'RE ALL PRETTY
TOUGH, AREN'T YOU?
STARSHIP,
PHASERBANKS.
WELL, YOU CAN'T
GET YOUR STARSHIP
DOWN IN THE TUNNELS.
I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GONNA NEED TO,
MR. APPEL.
MR. VANDERBERG,
I'LL NEED A COMPLETE
SUBSURFACE CHART
OF ALL THE DRIFTS,
GALLERIES, TUNNELS.
YOU'LL GET IT.
MR. VANDERBERG,
WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S A SILICON
NODULE.
THERE ARE A
MILLION OF THEM
ARE DOWN THERE.
NO COMMERCIAL
VALUE.
BUT A GEOLOGICAL ODDITY,
TO SAY THE LEAST.
PURE SILICON?
A FEW TRACE ELEMENTS.
LOOK, WE DIDN'T
CALL YOU HERE SO YOU
COULD COLLECT ROCKS.
THANK YOU,
MR. VANDERBERG.
WE'LL NEED YOUR
COMPLETE COOPERATION.
YOU'LL HAVE IT.
JUST FIND
THAT CREATURE,
WHATEVER IT IS.
I'VE GOT A QUOTA
TO MEET.
COME ON, APPEL.
VAST NUMBER OF TUNNELS
IS NOT GONNA MAKE
OUR HUNTING ANY EASIER.
DOC?
SCHMITTER DIDN'T
BURN TO DEATH, JIM,
NOT IN THE USUAL
SENSE, ANYWAY.
EXPLAIN THAT.
WELL, THERE ARE
ONLY FRAGMENTS
OF BONE AND TEETH LEFT,
BUT THE PLANT'S PHYSICIAN
AGREES WITH ME--
A CHEMICAL CORROSION...
ALMOST AS IF HE'D BEEN
THROWN INTO A VAT
OF EXTREMELY
CORROSIVE ACID.
STRONG ENOUGH
TO EAT MACHINERY?
STRONG ENOUGH TO EAT
ANYTHING ELSE
YOU CAN THINK OF.
MR. SPOCK.
I'VE CHARTED
THE POSITIONS
OF THE DEATHS
AND THE ACTS
OF SABOTAGE.
HERE, HERE,
AND HERE.
IF THE TIMES
OF THESE INCIDENTS
ARE TO BE ACCEPTED
AS ACCURATE,
THE CREATURE WOULD
HAVE TO HAVE MOVED
AT AN INCREDIBLE
RATE OF SPEED.
MM-HMM.
MR. VANDERBERG,
HOW RECENT ARE
THESE CHARTS?
THEY WERE MADE
LAST YEAR.
BEFORE
THE APPEARANCE OF
WHATEVER IT IS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I SEE.
MR. SPOCK...
GIVE US A REPORT
ON LIFE BENEATH
THE SURFACE.
WITHIN RANGE
OF OUR SENSORS,
THERE IS NO LIFE,
OTHER THAN
THE ACCOUNTABLE
HUMAN RESIDENTS
OF THIS COLONY
BENEATH THE SURFACE,
UH, AT LEAST, NO
LIFE AS WE KNOW IT.
WE CAN'T COVER
TUNNEL BY TUNNEL
ON FOOT.
WE MUST
GET PRODUCTION
GOING AGAIN.
WE MUST HAVE
THAT PERGIUM!
IF WE COULD FORCE
ANOTHER APPEARANCE
OF THIS CREATURE...
WHEN THAT CREATURE
APPEARS, MEN DIE.
[FIERY NOISE]
AAAAHHHH!
TOO MANY TUNNELS.
WE COULDN'T POSSIBLY.
MR. SPOCK, OUR SENSORS
CAN PICK UP
NORMAL LIFE FUNCTIONS
AT A CONSIDERABLE DISTANCE,
BUT WHAT ABOUT
ABNORMAL LIFE FUNCTIONS?
[SIREN BLARES]
SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING IN
THE REACTOR ROOM!
BACK TO YOUR STATIONS.
LOOK AT THAT.
I WOULDN'T
TOUCH IT, CAPTAIN.
AN EXTREMELY
ACTIVE CORROSIVE.
TRACES MAY LINGER.
KIRK! QUICKLY!
THE MAIN
CIRCULATING PUMP FOR
THE ENTIRE REACTOR--
IT'S GONE.
SAME INDICATION
AS SHOWN AT THE
DOOR, CAPTAIN--
VERY STRONG
CORROSIVE.
IS THERE A REPLACEMENT
FOR THAT?
NO. NONE.
IT'S OUTDATED.
WE'VE NEVER HAD
ANY TROUBLE WITH IT.
SPOCK, ONBOARD?
NOTHING FOR
A DEVICE
THIS ANTIQUATED,
CAPTAIN.
WITHOUT THE PUMP
MECHANISM,
THE REACTOR WILL
GO SUPERCRITICAL.
IT COULD POISON
HALF THE PLANET.
WE CAN'T
SHUT IT DOWN.
IT PROVIDES
HEAT AND AIR
AND LIFE SUPPORT
FOR THE WHOLE
COLONY.
MR. SPOCK, WE SEEM
TO HAVE BEEN GIVEN
A CHOICE--
DEATH BY ASPHYXIATION...
OR DEATH BY
RADIATION POISONING.
A PXK PERGIUM REACTOR?
NO, SIR. WE DON'T HAVE
ANY SPARE CIRCULATING PUMP
FOR A THING LIKE THAT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN
A PXK IN 20 YEARS.
CAN YOU RIG ONE UP?
IT'S VITAL.
WELL, SIR, I CAN
PUT TOGETHER
SOME ODDS AND ENDS,
BUT IT WON'T HOLD
FOR LONG.
HOW LONG?
48 HOURS MAYBE,
WITH A BIT OF LUCK.
48 HOURS IS BETTER
THAN NOTHING.
GET TOGETHER WHAT
YOU NEED AND BEAM
DOWN HERE WITH IT.
TOP PRIORITY.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
I'LL BE RIGHT DOWN.
SCOTT OUT.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
IT BREAKS DOWN?
HOPEFULLY WE'LL HAVE
FOUND THE MISSING
PART BY THEN.
HOPEFULLY?
SMALL CHANCE.
WE'LL HAVE TO,
CHIEF.
THE ALTERNATIVE
IS TO EVACUATE
ALL YOU PEOPLE UP
TO THE "ENTERPRISE."
A DOZEN PLANETS
DEPEND ON YOU
FOR PERGIUM
FOR THEIR REACTOR.
THEY'RE ALREADY
SCREAMING.
REACTORS
CLOSING DOWN, LIFE
SUPPORT SYSTEMS--
I'M CONCERNED
WITH MY PEOPLE
RIGHT HERE KIRK--
THEY'RE BEING MURDERED.
YOU FIND THAT MONSTER
AND KILL IT.
THE MISSING PUMP
WAS NOT TAKEN
BY ACCIDENT.
IT WAS THE ONE PIECE
OF EQUIPMENT
ABSOLUTELY ESSENTIAL
FOR THE OPERATION
OF THE REACTOR.
DO YOU THINK
THE CREATURE
IS TRYING TO PUSH
THE COLONISTS
OFF THE PLANET?
IT WOULD SEEM SO.
BUT WHY NOW, MR. SPOCK?
THESE PRODUCTION FACILITIES
HAVE BEEN IN OPERATION
FOR OVER 50 YEARS.
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT THERE IS
A POSSIBILITY.
WHAT'S THAT?
LIFE AS WE KNOW IT
IS UNIVERSALLY BASED
ON SOME COMBINATION
OF CARBON COMPOUNDS.
BUT WHAT IF LIFE EXISTS
BASED ON ANOTHER ELEMENT?
FOR INSTANCE...
SILICON?
YOU'RE CREATING
FANTASIES, MR. SPOCK.
NOT NECESSARILY, BONES.
I'VE HEARD OF THE
THEORETICAL POSSIBILITY
OF LIFE BASED
ON SILICON,
BUT SILICON-BASED LIFE
WOULD BE OF AN ENTIRELY
DIFFERENT ORDER.
IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT OUR PHASERS
MIGHT NOT AFFECT IT.
CERTAINLY NOT PHASER ONE,
WHICH IS FAR LESS
POWERFUL THAN PHASER TWO.
ALL RIGHT.
HOW ABOUT THIS--
A CREATURE THAT LIVES DEEP
IN THE PLANET BELOW US,
AT HOME IN SOLID ROCK.
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT
IN ORDER TO SURVIVE,
IT WOULD HAVE TO
HAVE SOME FORM
OF NATURAL ARMOR PLATING.
IT COULD EXPLAIN MUCH,
ESPECIALLY SINCE
THE COLONISTS ARE ARMED
ONLY WITH PHASER I.
BUT OUR PEOPLE HAVE
PHASER NUMBER TWO.
WHICH I COULD ADJUST
TO BE MORE EFFECTIVE
AGAINST SILICON.
SILICON-BASED LIFE
IS PHYSIOLOGICALLY
IMPOSSIBLE,
ESPECIALLY IN
AN OXYGEN ATMOSPHERE.
IT MAY BE, DOCTOR,
THAT THE CREATURE
CAN EXIST
FOR BRIEF PERIODS
IN SUCH AN ATMOSPHERE
BEFORE RETURNING
TO ITS OWN ENVIRONMENT.
I STILL THINK
YOU'RE IMAGINING THINGS.
YOU MAY
BE RIGHT, DOCTOR,
BUT AT LEAST IT'S
SOMETHING TO GO ON.
MR. SPOCK,
HAVE LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER GIOTTO
ASSEMBLE
THE SECURITY TROOPS
AND ARM THEM WITH
PHASER NUMBER TWO.
YOU MAKE THE PROPER
ADJUSTMENTS.
YOU SEEM FASCINATED
BY THIS ROCK.
YES, CAPTAIN.
YOU RECALL THAT
VANDERBERG COMMENTED
THERE WERE
THOUSANDS OF THESE
AT A LOWER LEVEL--
THE LEVEL WHICH
THE MACHINERY OPENED
JUST PRIOR
TO THE FIRST APPEARANCE
OF THE CREATURE.
DO THEY TIE IN?
I DON'T KNOW.
SPECULATE.
I HAVE ALREADY GIVEN
DR. McCOY SUFFICIENT
CAUSE FOR AMUSEMENT.
I WOULD PREFER TO COGITATE
THE POSSIBILITIES
FOR A TIME.
A SHORT TIME,
MR. SPOCK.
WE HAVE VERY LITTLE.
HOW'S IT GOING,
SCOTTY?
WELL, SIR, IT'S
A PLUMBER'S NIGHTMARE,
BUT IT'LL HOLD
FOR A BIT.
IT HAS TO HOLD
LONGER THAN
A BIT.
[BEEP BEEP]
I'M SORRY, SIR.
THAT'S ABOUT
THE BEST I CAN DO,
AND I GUARANTEE
IT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
KIRK HERE.
Spock: CAPTAIN,
SECURITY OFFICERS
HAVE GATHERED
IN CHIEF VANDERBERG'S
OFFICE.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
KIRK OUT.
SCOTTY,
RIDE HERD ON IT.
KIND WORDS.
TENDER, LOVING CARE.
KISS IT. BABY IT.
FLATTER IT
IF YOU HAVE TO,
BUT KEEP IT GOING.
I'LL DO WHAT
I CAN, SIR.
YOU'LL PROCEED
FROM LEVEL TO LEVEL,
CHECKING OUT
EVERY FOOT OF OPENING.
YOU ARE SEARCHING
FOR SOME SORT
OF CREATURE
WHICH IS HIGHLY RESISTANT
TO PHASER FIRE.
PHASERS WILL BE SET
ON MAXIMUM,
AND REMEMBER THIS--
50 PEOPLE HAVE DIED.
I WANT NO MORE DEATHS.
EXCEPT
THE BLOODY THING.
THE CREATURE
MAY OR MAY NOT
ATTACK ON SIGHT.
HOWEVER, YOU MUST.
IT IS VITALLY IMPORTANT
THAT WE GET THIS INSTALLATION
BACK INTO PRODUCTION.
MR. VANDERBERG,
MAY I ASK
AT WHICH LEVEL
YOU DISCOVERED
THE NODULES
OF SILICON?
THE 23rd. WHY?
COMMANDER GIOTTO,
TAKE YOUR DETAIL.
GO DIRECTLY TO
THE 23rd LEVEL.
START YOUR SEARCH THERE.
AYE AYE, SIR.
MAY I ASK
IF YOU HAVE REASON
TO SUSPECT THIS
CREATURE MAY BE
ON THAT LEVEL?
IT'S ONE OF
THE POSSIBILITIES
WE'VE DISCUSSED.
I WANT YOUR PEOPLE
TO STAY ON THE TOP LEVEL,
TOGETHER AND AT
A SAFE PLACE.
I DON'T KNOW ANY
SAFE PLACE, CAPTAIN,
THE WAY THAT THING
COMES AND GOES.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
YOU HAVE YOUR INSTRUCTIONS.
LET'S GET AT IT.
[SENSOR TONE]
MR. SPOCK?
FIND SOMETHING?
ADJUSTING MY TRICORDER
TO REGISTER FOR
SILICON, CAPTAIN.
[SENSOR TONE CONTINUES]
INTERESTING.
TRACES?
A LIFE FORM, CAPTAIN.
BEARING 111 DEGREES,
ELEVATION 4 DEGREES.
ONE OF OUR PEOPLE?
NO, SIR.
SILICON.
[FIERY NOISE]
AAAAAHHHH!
HE NEVER EVEN HAD
A CHANCE TO FIRE,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S ONLY
BEEN SECONDS SINCE
WE HEARD HIM SCREAM.
THE CREATURE MUST
STILL BE AROUND.
CAPTAIN.
THIS TUNNEL.
MY READINGS
INDICATE IT WAS MADE
WITHIN THE HOUR,
MOMENTS AGO,
IN FACT.
ARE YOU CERTAIN?
POSITIVE.
THIS TUNNEL GOES BACK
AS FAR AS THE EYE
CAN SEE.
OUR BEST MACHINERY
COULDN'T CUT A TUNNEL
LIKE THIS.
NOT EVEN
WITH PHASERS.
INDEED, CAPTAIN.
I'M QUITE AT A LOSS.
[FIERY NOISE]
GET DOWN.
DISAPPEARED.
ASTONISHING THAT
ANYTHING OF THAT BULK
COULD MOVE
SO RAPIDLY.
THESE WALLS ARE HOT.
INDEED.
THIS TUNNEL
WAS CUT
WITHIN THE LAST
TWO MINUTES.
YOU ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN?
YES. PERFECTLY.
DID YOU
SEE IT, SIR?
YES, WE SAW
WHERE DOES
THE TUNNEL GO?
READINGS INDICATE
A MAZE OF TUNNELS
OF THIS
GENERAL CATEGORY
IN THAT DIRECTION.
DID YOU GET A SHOT
AT IT?
YES. WE TOOK
A BITE OUT OF IT.
NOT ANIMAL TISSUE.
WHAT IS IT?
CLOSEST APPROXIMATION
I COULD COME TO
WOULD BE
FIBROUS ASBESTOS,
A MINERAL, CAPTAIN.
THEN YOUR GUESS
WAS RIGHT.
IT WOULD SEEM SO.
SILICON-BASED.
SUMMATION.
WE ARE DEALING WITH
A SILICON CREATURE
OF THE DEEP ROCKS,
CAPABLE OF MOVING
THROUGH SOLID ROCK
AS EASILY AS WE MOVE
THROUGH THE AIR.
THAT WOULD
ACCOUNT FOR
THE TUNNELS.
CORRECT.
THIS CREATURE'S BODY
SECRETES AN EXTREMELY
POWERFUL CORROSIVE.
POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO DISSOLVE THE DOOR
OF THE REACTOR CHAMBER.
AND IT EXPLAINS
THE MURDERED MEN.
IT'S DEFINITELY
PHASER RESISTANT.
WE HAD OUR WEAPONS
SET FOR SILICON
AND ON FULL POWER,
YET WE ONLY
DAMAGED IT.
IT STILL LIVES.
MEANING IT'S
IMPOSSIBLE TO KILL?
NO. NO,
IT MIGHT REQUIRE
AMASSED PHASERS.
OR A SINGLE PHASER
WITH MUCH LONGER CONTACT.
COMMANDER...
PASS THIS ON
TO YOUR MEN--
WE KNEW
IT WAS A KILLER.
NOW IT'S WOUNDED...
PROBABLY IN PAIN
SOMEWHERE
BACK THERE.
THERE'S NOTHING
MORE DANGEROUS THAN
A WOUNDED ANIMAL.
COMMANDER GIOTTO.
INSTRUCT YOUR MEN TO
CONCENTRATE THE SEARCH
IN THIS SECTOR.
REMIND THEM
THE CREATURE
IS WOUNDED.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
WHAT IS IT, SPOCK?
I'VE RUN A COMPLETE
SPHERICAL CHECK
ON ALL
LIFE FORMS, CAPTAIN,
RADIUS 100 MILES.
I'VE LOCATED OUR MEN,
ALL OF THEM,
AND I'VE LOCATED
ONE CREATURE
MOVING RAPIDLY
THROUGH NATIVE ROCK,
BEARING 201.
AND THAT IS ALL.
ONE CREATURE
IN 100 MILES?
EXACTLY.
CAPTAIN,
THERE ARE LITERALLY
THOUSANDS OF THESE TUNNELS
IN THIS GENERAL
AREA ALONE,
FAR TOO MANY TO BE CUT
BY THE ONE CREATURE
IN AN ORDINARY
LIFETIME.
THEN WE'RE
DEALING WITH MORE
THAN ONE CREATURE,
DESPITE YOUR
TRICORDER READINGS,
OR WE HAVE
A CREATURE
WITH AN EXTREMELY
LONG LIFE SPAN.
OR IT IS THE LAST
OF A RACE OF CREATURES
WHICH MADE THESE TUNNELS.
IF SO, IF IT IS
THE ONLY SURVIVOR
OF A DEAD RACE,
TO KILL IT WOULD BE
A CRIME AGAINST SCIENCE.
MR. SPOCK...
OUR MISSION IS
TO PROTECT THIS COLONY,
TO GET THE PERGIUM
MOVING AGAIN.
THIS IS NOT A
ZOOLOGICAL EXPEDITION.
MAINTAIN A CONSTANT
READING ON THE CREATURE.
IF WE HAVE TO,
WE'LL USE PHASERS
TO CUT OUR OWN TUNNELS.
WE'LL TRY
TO SURROUND IT.
I'M SORRY, MR. SPOCK,
BUT I'M AFRAID
THE CREATURE MUST DIE.
I SEE NO ALTERNATIVE
MYSELF, CAPTAIN.
IT MERELY SEEMS A PITY.
THE SEARCH TEAM IS
GATHERING IN THE MAIN TUNNEL.
GOOD.
SO IT IS WOUNDED, AND THEREFORE
TWICE AS DANGEROUS.
STAY IN PAIRS.
IF YOU SEE IT,
CONCENTRATE YOUR PHASER FIRE
AT WHAT APPEARS
TO BE ITS HEAD.
CONCENTRATE IT.
MAINTAIN IT.
IT IS DEFINITELY RESISTANT,
BUT IT CAN BE HURT.
AND IF IT CAN BE HURT,
IT CAN BE KILLED.
MISTER SPOCK.
GENTLEMEN, IF YOU'LL
EXAMINE YOUR CHARTS,
PLEASE.
I LAST LOCATED
THE CREATURE
IN THE AREA
MARKED ATTIT-26
MOVING IN BEARING 201.
THIS PARTICULAR GROUP
WILL MOVE OUT
BEYOND THAT AREA
IN ALL DIRECTIONS
IN AN EFFORT
TO SURROUND IT,
POSSIBLY CAPTURE IT.
YOUR ORDERS ARE
SHOOT TO KILL.
PROTECT YOURSELF
AT ALL TIMES.
COMMANDER GIOTTO,
DISPERSE YOUR
SEARCH PARTIES.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
LOUIS, VINZI,
TAKE YOUR MEN OUT.
MR. SPOCK.
CAPTURE IT?
I DON'T RECALL GIVING
ANY SUCH ORDER.
YOU DID NOT, SIR.
I MERELY THOUGHT THAT IF
THE OPPORTUNITY AROSE--
I WILL LOSE
NO MORE MEN.
THE CREATURE WILL
BE KILLED ON SIGHT
AND THAT'S
THE END OF IT.
VERY WELL, SIR.
MR. SPOCK.
I WANT YOU
TO ASSIST SCOTTY
IN MAINTAINING
THAT MAKESHIFT
CIRCULATING PUMP.
I--I BEG YOUR PARDON, SIR?
YOU HEARD ME. IT'S
VITAL THAT WE KEEP THAT
REACTOR IN OPERATION.
YOUR SCIENTIFIC
KNOWLEDGE--
IS NOT NEEDED THERE, SIR.
MR. SCOTT HAS
FAR MORE KNOWLEDGE
OF NUCLEAR REACTORS
THAN I DO.
YOU'RE AWARE OF THAT.
MR. SPOCK, YOU
ARE SECOND IN COMMAND.
THIS WILL BE
A DANGEROUS HUNT.
EITHER ONE OF US
BY HIMSELF
IS EXPENDABLE.
BOTH OF US ARE NOT.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE
APPROXIMATELY 100 OF US
ENGAGED IN THIS SEARCH
AGAINST ONE CREATURE.
THE ODDS AGAINST
YOU AND I BOTH BEING
KILLED ARE 2,228.7 TO 1.
2,228.7 TO 1?
THOSE ARE
PRETTY GOOD ODDS,
MR. SPOCK.
AND THEY ARE
OF COURSE ACCURATE,
CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE.
WELL, I HATE
TO USE THE WORD,
BUT LOGICALLY,
WITH THOSE KIND
OF ODDS,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
STAY.
BUT PLEASE STAY
OUT OF TROUBLE,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS ALWAYS
MY INTENTION, CAPTAIN.
[BEEP BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
SCOTTY HERE, CAPTAIN.
MY BRILLIANT IMPROVISATION
JUST GAVE UP THE GHOST.
IT COULDN'T
STAND THE STRAIN.
CAN YOU
FIX IT AGAIN?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S GONE FOR GOOD.
START IMMEDIATE
EVACUATION OF
ALL COLONISTS
TO THE "ENTERPRISE."
NOT ALL, CAPTAIN.
I AND SOME OF MY
KEY PERSONNEL ARE STAYING.
WE'LL BE DOWN
TO JOIN YOU.
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
PHASERS FOR YOU.
THEN WE'LL USE CLUBS.
WE'RE NOT BEING CHASED
AWAY FROM HERE.
WE'RE STAYING.
GOOD. GET EVERYBODY ELSE
ABOARD THE "ENTERPRISE."
THE FEWER PEOPLE WE HAVE
BREATHING THE AIR
DOWN HERE,
THE LONGER
THE REST OF US WILL BE
ABLE TO HOLD OUT.
HOW MUCH LONGER, SCOTTY?
THE REACTOR WILL
GO SUPERCRITICAL
IN ABOUT
10 HOURS, SIR.
YOU HAVE THAT
LONG TO FIND
THE MECHANISM.
WE'LL DO OUR BEST.
START FEEDING US
CONSTANT STATUS REPORTS,
SCOTTY.
VANDERBERG, YOU
AND YOUR CREW ASSEMBLE
AT LEVEL 23,
CHECKPOINT TIGER.
KIRK OUT.
TEAM UP WITH
THE "ENTERPRISE"
SECURITY PERSONNEL.
THEY'RE BETTER ARMED
THAN YOU ARE.
KEEP SOMEONE IN SIGHT
AT ALL TIMES.
VANDERBERG, TAKE TWO MEN.
GO THROUGH
THAT TUNNEL THERE.
RENDEZVOUS
WITH COMMANDER GIOTTO.
APPEL AND THE REST
OF THE MEN,
GO THROUGH THERE.
TIE UP WITH
LIEUTENANT OSBORNE'S DETAIL.
MR. SPOCK AND I WILL
CONTROL THE OPERATION
FROM A CENTRAL POINT.
THAT'S ALL.
MR. SPOCK?
CAPTAIN, WE ARE
BEING WATCHED.
ARE YOU SURE?
INTUITION?
NO, SIR.
WE'RE BEING WATCHED.
[ELECTRONIC TONE]
CAPTAIN.
FRESH READINGS
WITHIN THE HOUR
IN EACH OF THESE TUNNELS.
CHART SAYS
BOTH OF THESE
TUNNELS CONVERGE
A FEW THOUSAND
YARDS FURTHER.
YOU TAKE A LEFT.
I'LL TAKE
A RIGHT.
SHOULD WE SEPARATE?
TWO TUNNELS.
TWO OF US.
WE SEPARATE.
MR. SPOCK.
YES, CAPTAIN.
I'VE FOUND A WHOLE LAYER
OF THESE SILICON NODULES
OF YOURS,
HUNDREDS OF THEM.
Spock: INDEED?
I FIND THAT MOST
ILLUMINATING, CAPTAIN.
BE ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN
YOU DO NOT DAMAGE
ANY OF THEM.
EXPLAIN.
ONLY A THEORY I HAVE.
[RUMBLING]
CAPTAIN?
Spock:
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
JIM?
JIM!
YES, MR. SPOCK.
ALL RIGHT.
WE...SEEM TO HAVE
HAD A CAVE-IN.
I COULD PHASER YOU OUT.
Kirk: NO.
NO, NO, YOU BETTER NOT.
ANY DISTURBANCE MIGHT
BRING DOWN THE REST
OF THE WALL.
BESIDES, IT ISN'T NECESSARY.
THE CHART SAID THE TUNNELS
MEET FURTHER ON.
VERY WELL,
BUT I FIND IT
EXTREMELY DISQUIETING
THAT YOUR ROOF
CHOSE THAT PARTICULAR
MOMENT TO COLLAPSE.
PLEASE PROCEED
WITH EXTREME CAUTION.
I SHALL QUICKEN MY PACE.
VERY WELL, MR. SPOCK.
I'LL MEET YOU
AT THE OTHER END--
[RUMBLING]
[BEEP BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, I JUST READ
SOME FRESH SIGNS.
THE CREATURE IS
IN THIS AREA.
I'LL TAKE
A LIFEFORM READING.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY,
MR. SPOCK.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHERE
THE CREATURE IS.
WHERE, CAPTAIN?
10 FEET AWAY FROM ME.
KILL IT, CAPTAIN,
QUICKLY.
IT'S NOT MAKING
ANY THREATENING
MOVES, SPOCK.
YOU DON'T DARE
TAKE THE CHANCE,
CAPTAIN.
KILL IT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
THE ONE THAT WANTED IT
KEPT ALIVE.
CAPTURED IF POSSIBLE.
JIM, YOUR LIFE IS
IN DANGER.
YOU CAN'T TAKE THE RISK.
IT SEEMS
TO BE WAITING.
I REMIND YOU
IT IS A PROVEN KILLER.
I'M ON MY WAY.
SPOCK OUT.
WELL...
WHAT DO WE DO,
JUST...TALK IT OVER?
WELL, YOU CAN BE HURT,
CAN'T YOU?
WE JUST SIT HERE?
IT'S YOUR MOVE.
NO, NO! DON'T SHOOT.
COME ON OVER,
MR. SPOCK.
FASCINATING.
IT'S MADE NO MOVES
AGAINST YOU.
NO. IT SEEMS
TO BE WAITING.
I TRIED TALKING TO IT,
BUT IT DIDN'T DO ANY GOOD.
YES...
THEY'RE ALL
THROUGH HERE,
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THOUSANDS OF THEM.
YES, I SEE.
IT MEANS
SOMETHING TO YOU?
POSSIBLY THE ANSWER,
CAPTAIN,
BUT I'M NOT CERTAIN.
CAPTAIN, YOU ARE AWARE
OF THE VULCAN TECHNIQUE
OF THE JOINING
OF TWO MINDS.
YOU THINK YOU CAN GET
THROUGH TO THAT THING?
POSSIBLE.
MR. SPOCK...
I KNOW IT'S A...
TERRIBLE PERSONAL LOWERING
OF MENTAL BARRIERS...
BUT IF THERE'S A CHANCE...
I'LL TRY.
AAH!
PAIN!
THAT'S ALL I GOT,
CAPTAIN...
WAVES AND WAVES
OF SEARING PAIN.
IT'S IN AGONY.
[FIERY NOISE]
"NO KILL I."
WHAT IS THAT,
A PLEA FOR US
NOT TO KILL IT,
OR A PROMISE THAT
IT WON'T KILL US?
I DON'T KNOW,
CAPTAIN.
EVIDENTLY, IT
GAINED AN IMMEDIATE
KNOWLEDGE OF US
FROM ITS EMPATHY
WITH ME.
IN MY BRIEF
CONTACT WITH THE
CREATURE'S MIND,
I DISCOVERED
IT IS A HIGHLY
INTELLIGENT,
EXTREMELY
SOPHISTICATED
ANIMAL...
IN GREAT PAIN,
OF COURSE, BECAUSE
OF ITS WOUND,
BUT NOT REACTING
AT ALL LIKE
A WOUNDED CREATURE.
IT CALLS ITSELF
A HORTA.
A HORTA!
MR. SPOCK, WE NEED THAT
RETARDATION MECHANISM.
YOU MUST REESTABLISH
COMMUNICATIONS WITH IT.
CAPTAIN, IT HAS NO
REASON TO GIVE US
THE DEVICE,
AND APPARENTLY
EVERY REASON
FOR WISHING US
OFF THIS PLANET.
YES, I'M AWARE OF THAT.
IF WE COULD ONLY
WIN ITS CONFIDENCE.
DOCTOR McCOY,
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
McCOY: YES, CAPTAIN?
GRAB YOUR MEDICAL KIT
AND COME DOWN HERE
ON THE DOUBLE.
I'VE GOT A PATIENT
FOR YOU.
IS SOMEBODY INJURED?
WHAT HAPPENED?
NEVER MIND.
JUST COME DOWN
TO THE 23rd LEVEL.
YOU'LL BE LED TO US
BY TRICORDER READINGS.
KIRK OUT.
JIM, I REMIND YOU
THAT THIS IS
A SILICON-BASED
FORM OF LIFE.
DR. McCOY'S
MEDICAL KNOWLEDGE
WILL BE
TOTALLY USELESS.
HE'S A HEALER,
LET HIM HEAL.
MR. SPOCK, YOU MUST
RE-ESTABLISH COMMUNICATIONS.
I WANT TO KNOW WHY IT
SUDDENLY TOOK TO MURDER.
TO OBTAIN THAT KIND
OF COMMUNICATION,
CAPTAIN,
IT WILL BE NECESSARY
TO TOUCH IT.
WE HAVE SEEN HOW
THE CREATURE DESTROYS.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER GIOTTO.
GIOTTO HERE,
CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
PERFECTLY ALL RIGHT.
WHERE ARE YOU?
WE'RE AT THE END
OF THE TUNNEL.
A MR. VANDERBERG AND
HIS MEN ARE HERE,
AND THEY'RE
PRETTY UGLY.
SHALL I
LET THEM THROUGH?
UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
ALLOW THEM IN HERE YET.
THE MINUTE
DOC McCOY GETS THERE,
SEND HIM THROUGH.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
PITY!
THE THOUSANDS...
DEVILS!
ETERNITY ENDS...
THE CHAMBER OF THE AGES...
THE ALTAR OF TOMORROW!
Spock:
MURDERERS!
STOP THEM!
KILL!
STRIKE BACK!
MONSTERS!
WHAT IN THE NAME OF...
WHAT IS SPOCK DOING?
IT'S WOUNDED--BADLY.
YOU'VE GOT TO HELP IT.
HELP THAT?
GO TAKE A LOOK.
Spock:
THE END OF LIFE...
MURDERERS.
YOU CAN'T BE SERIOUS.
THAT THING IS VIRTUALLY
MADE OUT OF STONE!
HELP IT. TREAT IT.
I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT A BRICKLAYER.
YOU'RE A HEALER.
THERE'S A PATIENT.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
MR. SPOCK...
TELL IT WE'RE TRYING TO HELP.
THE MECHANISM.
UNDERSTOOD.
IS THE END OF LIFE...
ETERNITY STOPS...
GO OUT...
INTO THE TUNNEL.
TO THE CHAMBER...
OF THE AGES.
CRY FOR
THE CHILDREN.
WALK CAREFULLY
IN THE VAULT
OF TOMORROW.
SORROW FOR
THE MURDERED
CHILDREN.
THE THING YOU
SEARCH FOR IS THERE.
GO.
SADNESS.
SADNESS...
FOR THE END OF THINGS.
GO...
INTO THE TUNNEL.
THERE IS A PASSAGEWAY.
QUICKLY, QUICKLY.
THE CAPTAIN SAID FOR YOU
TO WAIT HERE,
AND HERE IS WHERE
YOU'RE GONNA WAIT.
THAT MURDERING
MONSTER'S IN THERE
AND WE'RE GOING TO
GO IN THERE AND KILL IT.
YOU'RE GOING
TO STAY HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT, LIEUTENANT.
JUST BEAM IT DOWN
TO ME IMMEDIATELY,
AND NEVER MIND
WHAT I WANT IT FOR.
I JUST WANT IT!
NOW MOVE!
IT IS TIME...
TO SLEEP.
IT IS OVER.
FAILURE.
THE MURDERERS...
HAVE WON.
DEATH IS WELCOME.
LET IT END...
HERE.
MR. SPOCK...
SPOCK...
COME OUT OF IT.
I FOUND THE UNIT
IN THERE.
IT'S
IN PRETTY GOOD SHAPE.
I ALSO FOUND ABOUT
A MILLION OF THESE...
SILICON NODULES.
THEY'RE EGGS,
AREN'T THEY?
YES, CAPTAIN, EGGS...
AND ABOUT TO HATCH.
MINERS MUST HAVE BROKEN
INTO THE HATCHERY.
THEIR OPERATIONS
DESTROYED THOUSANDS.
NO WONDER.
THERE. THEY'RE COMING.
ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO!
COME ON.
HOW ARE YOU DOING, DOC?
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
[RUNNING FOOTSTEPS]
NO, DON'T FIRE.
KILL IT!
FIRST MAN THAT FIRES
IS DEAD.
THAT THING HAS KILLED
50 OF MY MEN.
YOU'VE KILLED THOUSANDS
OF HER CHILDREN.
WHAT?
THOSE ROUND SILICON
NODULES YOU'VE BEEN
COLLECTING
AND DESTROYING?
THEY'RE HER EGGS.
TELL THEM, MR. SPOCK.
THERE HAVE BEEN
MANY GENERATIONS
OF HORTA ON THIS PLANET.
EVERY 50,000 YEARS,
THE ENTIRE RACE DIES,
ALL BUT ONE,
LIKE THIS ONE,
BUT THE EGGS LIVE.
SHE CARES FOR THEM...
PROTECTS THEM.
AND WHEN THEY HATCH,
SHE IS THE MOTHER TO THEM,
THOUSANDS OF THEM.
THIS CREATURE HERE IS
THE MOTHER OF HER RACE.
THE HORTA IS INTELLIGENT...
PEACEFUL...
MILD.
SHE HAD NO OBJECTION
TO SHARING THIS PLANET
WITH YOU,
TILL YOU BROKE
INTO HER NURSERY
AND STARTED
DESTROYING HER EGGS.
THEN SHE FOUGHT BACK
THE ONLY WAY SHE KNEW HOW,
AS ANY MOTHER WOULD FIGHT
WHEN HER CHILDREN
ARE IN DANGER.
WE DIDN'T KNOW.
HOW COULD WE?
YOU MEAN,
IF THESE EGGS HATCH,
THERE'LL BE THOUSANDS
OF THOSE THINGS
CRAWLING AROUND
DOWN HERE?
THIS IS WHERE THEY LIVE.
THEY DIGEST ROCK.
THEY TUNNEL
FOR NOURISHMENT.
AND THEY ARE
THE MOST INOFFENSIVE
OF CREATURES.
THEY HARBOR ILL WILL
TOWARD NO ONE..
LOOK, WE HAVE
PERGIUM TO DELIVER.
YES, I KNOW.
HERE'S YOUR
CIRCULATING PUMP.
YOU'VE COMPLAINED
THIS PLANET IS
A MINERALOGICAL
TREASURE HOUSE
IF YOU HAD THE EQUIPMENT
TO GET AT IT.
GENTLEMEN, THE HORTA
MOVES THROUGH ROCK
THE WAY WE MOVE THROUGH
AIR, AND IT LEAVES TUNNELS.
THE GREATEST NATURAL MINERS
IN THE UNIVERSE.
IT SEEMS TO ME WE COULD
MAKE AN AGREEMENT,
REACH A MODUS VIVENDI.
THEY TUNNEL.
YOU COLLECT AND PROCESS,
AND YOUR PROCESS OPERATION
WOULD BE A THOUSAND TIMES
MORE PROFITABLE.
IT SOUNDS ALL RIGHT
IF IT WILL WORK.
EXCEPT FOR ONE THING.
THE HORTA IS
BADLY WOUNDED.
IT MAY DIE.
IT WON'T DIE!
BY GOLLY, JIM,
I'M BEGINNING TO THINK
I CAN CURE A RAINY DAY.
CAN YOU HELP IT?
HELP IT? I CURED IT.
HOW?
I HAD THE SHIP BEAM DOWN
100 POUNDS OF THAT
THERMAL CONCRETE.
YOU KNOW, THE KIND
WE USE TO BUILD
EMERGENCY SHELTERS
OUT OF.
IT'S MOSTLY SILICONE.
SO I JUST TROWELED IT
INTO THE WOUND
AND IT'LL
ACT LIKE A BANDAGE
UNTIL IT HEALS.
TAKE A LOOK.
IT'S AS GOOD AS NEW.
WELL, SPOCK, I'M GONNA
HAVE TO ASK YOU
TO GET IN TOUCH
WITH THE HORTA AGAIN.
TELL HER OUR PROPOSITION.
SHE AND HER CHILDREN
CAN DO ALL THE TUNNELING
THEY WANT.
OUR PEOPLE WILL
REMOVE THE MINERALS,
AND EACH SIDE WILL
LEAVE THE OTHER ALONE.
THINK SHE'LL GO FOR IT?
IT SEEMS LOGICAL,
CAPTAIN.
THE HORTA HAS
A VERY LOGICAL MIND.
AND AFTER
CLOSE ASSOCIATION
WITH HUMANS,
I FIND THAT
CURIOUSLY REFRESHING.
SHIP READY TO LEAVE
ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
COURSE LAID IN.
VERY GOOD,
MR. SPOCK.
CHIEF ENGINEER
VANDERBERG STANDING BY
ON CHANNEL 1.
FINE.
YES, CHIEF.
KIRK HERE.
JUST WANTED
TO TELL YOU THE EGGS
HAVE STARTED
TO HATCH, CAPTAIN.
FIRST THING
THE LITTLE DEVILS DO
IS START TO TUNNEL.
WE'VE ALREADY HIT
HUGE NEW PERGIUM
DEPOSITS.
I'M AFRAID TO TELL
YOU HOW MUCH
GOLD AND PLATINUM
AND RARE EARTHS
WE'VE UNCOVERED.
I'M DELIGHTED
TO HEAR THAT, CHIEF.
ONCE MOTHER HORTA
TELLS HER KIDS
WHAT TO LOOK FOR,
YOU PEOPLE ARE GONNA BE
EMBARRASSINGLY RICH.
YOU KNOW, THE HORTA
AREN'T SO BAD
ONCE YOU GET USED
TO THEIR APPEARANCE.
THAT'S ABOUT IT, KIRK.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
OUR PLEASURE, CHIEF.
KIRK OUT.
CURIOUS.
WHAT CHIEF VANDERBERG
SAID ABOUT THE HORTA
IS EXACTLY WHAT
THE MOTHER HORTA SAID TO ME.
SHE FOUND HUMANOID
APPEARANCE REVOLTING,
BUT SHE THOUGHT
SHE COULD GET USED TO IT.
OH, SHE DID,
DID SHE?
TELL ME, DID SHE
HAPPEN TO MAKE
ANY COMMENT
ABOUT THOSE EARS?
NOT SPECIFICALLY.
BUT I DID GET
THE DISTINCT IMPRESSION
SHE FOUND THEM
THE MOST ATTRACTIVE HUMAN
CHARACTERISTIC OF ALL.
I DIDN'T HAVE THE HEART
TO TELL HER
THAT ONLY I HAVE--
SHE REALLY LIKED
THOSE EARS?
CAPTAIN, THE HORTA
IS A REMARKABLY INTELLIGENT
AND SENSITIVE CREATURE
WITH IMPECCABLE TASTE.
BECAUSE SHE APPROVED
OF YOU.
REALLY, CAPTAIN,
MY MODESTY...
DOES NOT BEAR CLOSE
EXAMINATION, MR. SPOCK.
I SUSPECT YOU'RE
BECOMING MORE AND MORE
HUMAN ALL THE TIME.
YOU...
CAPTAIN, I SEE NO REASON
TO STAND HERE
AND BE INSULTED.
AHEAD, WARP FACTOR 2.