CAPTAIN, WE'VE REACHED
THE DESIGNATED POSITION
FOR SCANNING
THE CODED DIRECTIVE.
GOOD.
WE'VE BOTH
GUESSED RIGHT.
NEGOTIATIONS WITH
THE KLINGON EMPIRE
ARE ON THE VERGE
OF BREAKING DOWN.
STARFLEET COMMAND
ANTICIPATES
A SURPRISE ATTACK.
WE ARE TO PROCEED
TO ORGANIA
AND TAKE WHATEVER
STEPS ARE NECESSARY
TO PREVENT
THE KLINGONS
FROM USING IT
AS A BASE.
STRATEGICALLY SOUND.
ORGANIA IS THE ONLY
CLASS "M" PLANET
IN THE DISPUTED AREA,
IDEALLY LOCATED
FOR USE BY EITHER SIDE.
ORGANIA'S DESCRIPTION,
MR. SPOCK.
INHABITED
BY HUMANOIDS,
A VERY PEACEFUL,
FRIENDLY PEOPLE
LIVING ON
A PRIMITIVE LEVEL.
LITTLE OF
INTRINSIC VALUE.
APPROXIMATELY
CLASS "D-"
ON RICHTER'S SCALE
OF CULTURES.
ANOTHER ARMENIA, BELGIUM.
SIR?
THE WEAK INNOCENTS.
THEY ALWAYS SEEM TO BE
LOCATED ON THE NATURAL
INVASION ROUTES.
CAPTAIN, THE AUTOMATIC DEFLECTOR
SCREEN JUST POPPED ON.
BODY APPROACHING.
CONFIGURATION,
MR. SULU.
PHASER BANKS. LOCK ON.
RETURN FIRE.
MAINTAIN FIRING RANGE.
100% DISPERSAL PATTERN.
WE'VE HIT HIM, CAPTAIN.
HE'S HURT.
DAMAGE CONTROL, REPORT
TO THE FIRST OFFICER.
CAPTAIN, THE OTHER SHIP
DOESN'T REGISTER.
ONLY DRIFTING DEBRIS.
WE GOT HIM.
ALL HANDS,
MAINTAIN GENERAL ALERT.
HOLD BATTLE STATIONS.
DAMAGE REPORT, MR. SPOCK.
MINOR, CAPTAIN.
WE WERE MOST FORTUNATE.
BLAST DAMAGE
IN DECKS 10 AND 11.
MINOR BUCKLING
IN THE ANTI-MATTER PODS.
CASUALTIES ARE LIGHT.
MAINTAIN SURVEILLANCE,
MR. SULU.
NO CONTACT, CAPTAIN.
HE BLEW UP, ALL RIGHT.
WELL, WE'VE BEEN
ANTICIPATING
AN ATTACK.
I'D SAY WHAT WE'VE
JUST EXPERIENCED
VERY
NEARLY QUALIFIES.
YES. IT WOULD SEEM TO BE
AN UNFRIENDLY ACT.
AUTOMATIC
ALL-POINTS RELAY
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND,
CAPTAIN. CODE 1.
WELL, THERE IT IS--
WAR.
WE DIDN'T WANT IT,
BUT WE'VE GOT IT.
CURIOUS
HOW OFTEN YOU HUMANS
MANAGE TO OBTAIN THAT
WHICH YOU DO NOT WANT.
WAR OR NOT,
WE'VE STILL GOT
A JOB TO DO--
DENYING ORGANIA
TO THE KLINGONS.
WITH THE OUTBREAK
OF HOSTILITIES,
THAT MIGHT NOT BE EASY.
LAY IN A COURSE FOR
ORGANIA, MR. SULU.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
NEGOTIATING WITH THE ORGANIANS
WILL BE TIME-CONSUMING, CAPTAIN.
AND TIME IS THE ONE THING
WE'LL HAVE THE LEAST OF.
WELL, WE WON'T
GET IT BY TALKING
ABOUT IT, MR. SPOCK.
THE TRIGGER
HAS BEEN PULLED.
WE'VE GOT TO GET THERE
BEFORE THE HAMMER FALLS.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 7.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3198.4.
WE HAVE REACHED ORGANIA
AND ESTABLISHED
STANDARD ORBIT.
NO SIGNS OF HOSTILE
ACTIVITIES IN THIS AREA.
CAPTAIN...
UNIT X-Y 75847
REPORT A FLEET
OF KLINGON SHIPS
IN THEIR SECTOR,
SIR.
WHAT BEARING?
UNABLE
TO ASCERTAIN, SIR.
MR. SULU,
HAVE THE PHASER CREWS
STAND BY THEIR POSITIONS.
FULL POWER
DEFLECTOR SCREENS.
YES, SIR.
MR. SPOCK AND I
ARE GOING DOWN
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
YOU WILL BE IN COMMAND.
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY
IS TO THE ENTERPRISE,
NOT TO US.
IS THAT CLEAR?
PERFECTLY, SIR.
THE KLINGON FLEET
IS IN THIS QUADRANT.
WE KNOW THAT ORGANIA
WILL BE A TARGET.
IF THEY SHOULD EMERGE--
WE'LL HANDLE THEM, SIR.
YOU WILL EVALUATE
THE SITUATION.
IF THERE IS
A FLEET OF THEM,
YOU'LL GET OUT
OF HERE, MR. SULU.
BUT, CAPTAIN--
NO BUTS.
YOU'LL GET TO SAFETY
AND ALERT THE FLEET.
YOU WILL NOT ATTACK
ALONE.
MR. SPOCK AND I
WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
MR. SPOCK,
LET'S YOU AND I
PAY THE ORGANIANS
A VISIT.
YOU'D THINK THEY HAD PEOPLE
BEAMING DOWN EVERY DAY.
YES. CURIOUS
LACK OF INTEREST.
NOTICE THE RUINS IN
THE DISTANCE, CAPTAIN.
QUITE LARGE.
YES. A FORTRESS, PERHAPS.
A CASTLE.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT WOULD SEEM
TO BE INCONSISTENT
WITH THE REPORTS
WE'VE BEEN GIVEN
ON THIS CULTURE.
WELCOME.
RECEPTION COMMITTEE?
SEEMS SO.
YOU ARE OUR VISITORS.
WELCOME. WELCOME.
I AM AYELBORNE.
I AM CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE,
REPRESENTING THE UNITED
FEDERATION OF PLANETS.
THIS IS MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
YOU'RE MOST WELCOME,
MY FRIEND.
I WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK
TO SOMEONE IN AUTHORITY.
WE...WE DON'T HAVE
ANYBODY IN AUTHORITY,
BUT I AM THE CHAIRMAN
OF THE COUNCIL OF ELDERS.
PERHAPS I WOULD DO.
YOU PEOPLE ARE
IN GREAT DANGER.
IS THERE SOMEPLACE
WE CAN GO AND TALK?
OH, YES. OUR COUNCIL CHAMBERS
ARE NEARBY. PLEASE.
CAPTAIN,
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I SHOULD LIKE TO WANDER
ABOUT THE VILLAGE
AND MAKE SOME STUDIES.
OF COURSE, MY FRIEND.
OUR VILLAGE IS YOURS.
CAPTAIN.
GENTLEMEN, MY GOVERNMENT
HAS INFORMED ME
THAT THE KLINGONS
ARE EXPECTED TO MOVE
AGAINST YOUR PLANET
WITH THE OBJECTIVE OF MAKING IT
A BASE OF OPERATION
AGAINST THE FEDERATION.
MY MISSION, FRANKLY, IS...
TO KEEP THEM
FROM DOING IT.
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING, CAPTAIN,
IS THAT WE SEEM TO HAVE A CHOICE
BETWEEN DEALING WITH YOU
OR YOUR ENEMIES.
NO, SIR.
WITH THE FEDERATION,
YOU HAVE A CHOICE.
YOU HAVE NONE
WITH THE KLINGONS.
THE KLINGONS ARE
A MILITARY DICTATORSHIP.
WAR IS THEIR WAY OF LIFE.
LIFE UNDER THE KLINGON RULE
WOULD BE VERY UNPLEASANT.
WE OFFER YOU PROTECTION.
WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
ALTRUISTIC OFFER, CAPTAIN,
BUT WE REALLY DO NOT
NEED YOUR PROTECTION.
WE ARE A SIMPLE
PEOPLE, CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE NOTHING
THAT ANYBODY COULD WANT.
YOU HAVE THIS PLANET AND
ITS STRATEGIC LOCATION.
I ASSURE YOU THAT
IF YOU DON'T TAKE
ACTION TO PREVENT IT,
THE KLINGONS
WILL MOVE AGAINST YOU
JUST AS SURELY
AS YOUR SUN RISES.
WE WILL HELP YOU
BUILD DEFENSES,
BUILD FACILITIES.
WE HAVE NO DEFENSES,
CAPTAIN, NOR ARE ANY NEEDED.
GENTLEMEN...
I HAVE SEEN
WHAT THE KLINGONS DO
TO PLANETS LIKE YOURS.
THEY ARE ORGANIZED INTO
VAST SLAVE LABOR CAMPS.
NO FREEDOMS WHATSOEVER.
YOUR GOODS
WILL BE CONFISCATED.
HOSTAGES TAKEN, KILLED.
YOUR LEADERS CONFINED.
BE FAR BETTER OFF
ON A PENAL PLANET.
INFINITELY BETTER OFF.
CAPTAIN, WE SEE
THAT YOUR CONCERN
IS GENUINE.
WE ARE MOVED.
BUT AGAIN WE ASSURE YOU THAT WE
ARE IN ABSOLUTELY NO DANGER.
IF ANYBODY'S IN DANGER,
YOU ARE.
THAT CONCERNS US GREATLY.
IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF YOU RETURNED TO YOUR SHIP
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
YOU KEEP INSISTING
THAT THERE'S NO DANGER.
I KEEP ASSURING YOU
THAT THERE IS. WOULD YOU
MIND TELLING ME--
IT IS OUR WAY OF LIFE,
CAPTAIN.
THAT'S THE FIRST THING
THAT WOULD BE LOST.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M A SOLDIER,
NOT A DIPLOMAT.
I CAN ONLY TELL YOU
THE TRUTH.
IF YOU WILL
EXCUSE US, CAPTAIN,
WE WILL DISCUSS
YOUR KIND OFFER.
YES, CERTAINLY.
CAPTAIN, OUR INFORMATION
ON THESE PEOPLE
AND THEIR CULTURE
WAS NOT CORRECT.
THIS IS NOT
A PRIMITIVE SOCIETY
MAKING PROGRESS
TOWARD MECHANIZATION.
THEY ARE
TOTALLY STAGNANT.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE
OF ANY PROGRESS
AS FAR BACK AS MY
TRICORDER CAN REGISTER.
THAT DOESN'T SEEM LIKELY.
NEVERTHELESS,
IT IS TRUE.
FOR TENS OF THOUSANDS
OF YEARS,
THERE HAS BEEN
ABSOLUTELY
NO ADVANCEMENT,
NO SIGNIFICANT CHANGE
IN THEIR PHYSICAL
ENVIRONMENT.
THIS IS
A LABORATORY SPECIMEN
OF AN ARRESTED CULTURE.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
THAT MIGHT BE USEFUL.
WE HAVE DISCUSSED
YOUR OFFER, CAPTAIN,
AND OUR OPINION
IS UNCHANGED.
WE ARE IN NO DANGER.
WE THANK YOU FOR
YOUR KIND OFFER
OF ASSISTANCE,
ALTHOUGH WE MUST
DECLINE IT,
AND WE STRONGLY RECOMMEND
THAT YOU LEAVE ORGANIA
BEFORE YOU YOURSELVES
ARE ENDANGERED.
GENTLEMEN, I MUST
GET YOU TO RECONSIDER.
WE CAN BE OF IMMENSE
HELP TO YOU.
IN ADDITION
TO MILITARY AID,
WE CAN SEND YOU
SPECIALISTS, TECHNICIANS.
WE CAN SHOW YOU HOW TO
FEED A THOUSAND PEOPLE
WHERE ONE WAS FED BEFORE.
WE CAN HELP YOU BUILD
SCHOOLS, EDUCATE THE YOUNG
IN THE LATEST TECHNOLOGICAL
AND SCIENTIFIC SKILLS.
YOUR PUBLIC FACILITIES
ARE ALMOST NONEXISTENT.
WE CAN HELP YOU
REMAKE YOUR WORLD,
END DISEASE,
HUNGER, HARDSHIP.
AND ALL WE ASK IN RETURN
IS THAT
YOU LET US HELP YOU...
NOW.
CAPTAIN, I CAN SEE
THAT YOU DO NOT
UNDERSTAND US.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
KIRK HERE.
[SULU] CAPTAIN,
A LARGE NUMBER
OF KLINGON VESSELS
HAVE JUST ARRIVED.
THEY'RE OPENING FIRE.
[KIRK] POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION?
YES, SIR.
MY SCREENS ARE UP.
I CAN'T DROP THEM
TO BEAM YOU ABOARD.
MR. SULU,
FOLLOW YOUR ORDERS.
GET OUT OF HERE.
CONTACT THE FLEET.
RETURN IF THE ODDS
ARE MORE EQUAL.
KIRK OUT.
GENTLEMEN, YOU KEPT
INSISTING THAT THERE
WAS NO DANGER--
THAT IS CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS NO DANGER.
AYELBORNE.
8 SPACE VEHICLES
HAVE ASSUMED ORBIT
AROUND OUR PLANET.
THEY ARE ACTIVATING
THEIR MATERIAL
TRANSMISSION UNITS.
THANK YOU, TREFAYNE.
CAN YOU
VERIFY THAT?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN,
BUT IT SEEMS A LOGICAL
DEVELOPMENT.
CAPTAIN, SINCE IT IS
TOO LATE FOR YOU TO ESCAPE,
PERHAPS WE SHOULD DO SOMETHING
ABOUT PROTECTING YOU.
IF YOU HAD
LISTENED TO ME--
WE MUST BE SURE THAT
YOU ARE NOT HARMED.
AYELBORNE,
SEVERAL HUNDRED MEN
HAVE APPEARED
NEAR THE CITADEL.
THEY BRING
MANY WEAPONS.
HOW DOES HE KNOW THAT?
OH, OUR FRIEND TREFAYNE
IS REALLY QUITE INTUITIVE.
YOU CAN REST ASSURED
THAT WHAT HE SAYS
IS ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
SO, WE'RE STRANDED HERE
IN THE MIDDLE
OF A KLINGON OCCUPATION ARMY.
SO IT WOULD SEEM.
NOT A VERY
PLEASANT PROSPECT.
YOU HAVE A GIFT
FOR UNDERSTATEMENT,
MR. SPOCK.
IT'S NOT A VERY
PLEASANT PROSPECT AT ALL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3201.7.
MR. SPOCK AND I
ARE TRAPPED ON
THE PLANET ORGANIA,
WHICH IS IN THE PROCESS
OF BEING OCCUPIED
BY THE FORCES
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
THE ORGANIANS
HAVE PROVIDED US
WITH NATIVE CLOTHING
IN THE HOPES WE MAY BE
TAKEN FOR ORGANIANS.
CAPTAIN, OUR PHASERS
ARE GONE.
DID YOU TAKE THEM?
YES, CAPTAIN,
I TOOK THEM.
I MUST ASK YOU
TO RETURN THEM.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I CANNOT DO THAT.
WERE YOU ARMED, YOU MIGHT
BE TEMPTED TO USE VIOLENCE,
AND THAT
WE CANNOT PERMIT.
YOU, CAPTAIN, WILL PASS
AS AN ORGANIAN,
AND MR. SPOCK...
MR. SPOCK PRESENTS
A PROBLEM.
HE DOES NOT LOOK
LIKE AN ORGANIAN.
A VULCAN TRADER PERHAPS,
A DEALER IN KEVOSS
AND TRILIUM,
HARMLESS TO THE KLINGONS.
THEY KNOW THAT
VULCAN WAS A MEMBER
OF THE FEDERATION.
VULCAN MERCHANTS
ARE NOT UNCOMMON, CAPTAIN.
IT IS A PRACTICAL
APPROACH.
WHAT ABOUT
THE REST OF YOU?
WE SHOULD CONTINUE
AS BEFORE.
WE HAVE NOTHING TO FEAR.
YOU HAVE A LOT
TO LEARN...SIR.
AND IF I KNOW
THE KLINGONS,
YOU'LL BE LEARNING IT
THE HARD WAY.
THIS IS
THE RULING COUNCIL?
I AM AYELBORNE,
TEMPORARY HEAD
OF THE COUNCIL.
I BID YOU WELCOME.
NO DOUBT YOU DO.
I AM KOR, MILITARY
GOVERNOR OF ORGANIA.
WHO ARE YOU?
HE IS BARONA,
ONE OF OUR LEADING CITIZENS.
AND HE HAS NO TONGUE?
I HAVE A TONGUE.
GOOD.
YOU WILL BE TAUGHT
HOW TO USE IT.
WHERE IS YOUR SMILE?
MY WHAT?
THE STUPID, IDIOTIC
SMILE EVERYONE ELSE
SEEMS TO BE WEARING.
A VULCAN.
DO YOU ALSO
HAVE A TONGUE?
I AM SPOCK, A DEALER
IN KEVOSS AND TRILIUM.
YOU DO NOT LOOK
LIKE A STOREKEEPER.
TAKE THIS MAN.
VULCANS ARE MEMBERS
OF THE FEDERATION.
HE MAY BE A SPY.
HE'S NO SPY.
WELL...HAVE WE
A RAM AMONG THE SHEEP?
YOU OBJECT TO US
TAKING HIM?
HE'S DONE NOTHING.
NOTHING AT ALL.
COMING FROM AN ORGANIAN,
YOURS IS PRACTICALLY
AN ACT OF REBELLION.
VERY GOOD.
SO YOU WELCOME ME.
DO YOU ALSO WELCOME ME?
YOU'RE HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO ABOUT IT.
GOOD HONEST HATRED.
VERY REFRESHING.
HOWEVER, IT MAKES
NO DIFFERENCE
WHETHER
YOU WELCOME ME OR NOT.
I AM HERE,
AND I WILL STAY.
YOU ARE NOW SUBJECTS
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
YOU'LL FIND THERE ARE
MANY RULES AND REGULATIONS.
THEY WILL BE POSTED.
VIOLATION
OF THE SMALLEST OF THEM
WILL BE PUNISHED
BY DEATH.
WE SHALL OBEY
YOUR REGULATIONS, COMMANDER.
YOU DISAPPROVE, BARONA.
YOU NEED MY APPROVAL?
I NEED YOUR OBEDIENCE.
NOTHING MORE.
WILL I HAVE IT?
YOU SEEM TO BE
IN COMMAND.
YES...
I AM.
I SHALL NEED
A REPRESENTATIVE
FROM AMONG YOU,
LIAISON BETWEEN
THE FORCES OF THE OCCUPATION
AND THE CIVIL POPULATION.
SMILE AND SMILE.
I DON'T TRUST MEN
WHO SMILE TOO MUCH.
YOU, BARONA,
YOU'RE THE MAN.
ME? I DON'T
WANT THE JOB.
HAVE I ASKED WHETHER
OR NOT YOU WANT IT?
WE KLINGONS HAVE A REPUATION
FOR RUTHLESSNESS.
YOU WILL FIND
THAT IT IS DESERVED.
SHOULD ONE KLINGON
SOLDIER BE KILLED,
A THOUSAND ORGANIANS
WILL DIE.
I WILL HAVE ORDER.
IS THAT CLEAR?
COMMANDER,
I ASSURE YOU,
OUR PEOPLE WANT
NOTHING BUT PEACE.
WE SHALL CAUSE YOU
NO TROUBLE.
I'M SURE YOU WILL NOT.
TAKE THE VULCAN
TO THE EXAMINATION ROOM.
YOU, COME WITH ME.
I WILL FAMILIARIZE YOU
WITH YOUR NEW DUTIES.
WHAT ABOUT MR. SPOCK?
YOU ARE CONCERNED.
HE IS MY FRIEND.
YOU HAVE A POOR CHOICE
OF FRIENDS.
HE WILL BE
EXAMINED.
IF HE IS LYING,
HE WILL DIE.
IF HE IS TELLING
THE TRUTH...
HE WILL FIND THAT
BUSINESS HAS TAKEN
A TURN FOR THE WORSE.
TAKE HIM.
YOU DO NOT LIKE
TO BE PUSHED.
VERY GOOD.
YOU MAY BE A MAN
I CAN DEAL WITH, BARONA.
COME WITH ME.
"FROM THIS DAY ON,
"NO PUBLIC ASSEMBLAGES
OF MORE THAN THREE PEOPLE.
ALL PUBLICATIONS
TO BE CLEARED
THROUGH THIS OFFICE."
"NEIGHBORHOOD CONTROLS
WILL BE ESTABLISHED,
HOSTAGES SELECTED..."
A SOMEWHAT LENGTHY
LIST OF CRIMES
AGAINST THE STATE.
YOU DO NOT
LIKE THEM?
WELL?
HE IS WHAT
HE CLAIMS TO BE,
COMMANDER--
A VULCANIAN MERCHANT
NAMED SPOCK.
HIS MAIN CONCERN
SEEMS TO BE
HOW HE WOULD CARRY
OUT HIS BUSINESS
UNDER
OUR OCCUPATION.
NOTHING ELSE?
THE USUAL--
A CERTAIN AMOUNT
OF APPREHENSION
REGARDING US.
HIS MIND
IS REMARKABLY
DISCIPLINED.
YOU ARE SURE?
I USED FORCE 4...
WHICH IS SUFFICIENT
TO BREAK DOWN ANY PRETENSE.
VERY WELL,
LIEUTENANT.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TRY OUR LITTLE
TRUTH FINDER?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
IT'S A MIND SIFTER...
OR MIND RIPPER,
DEPENDING ON
HOW MUCH FORCE IS USED.
WE CAN RECORD
EVERY THOUGHT...
EVERY BIT OF KNOWLEDGE
IN A MAN'S MIND.
OF COURSE, WHEN
THAT MUCH FORCE IS USED,
THE MIND IS EMPTIED...
PERMANENTLY, I'M AFRAID.
WHAT'S LEFT IS MORE
VEGETABLE THAN HUMAN.
AND YOU'RE PROUD OF IT.
IT IS A TOOL...
A WEAPON.
SOMEWHAT DRASTIC,
BUT VERY EFFICIENT.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
PERFECTLY, BARONA.
BUT IT WAS
AN INTERESTING EXPERIENCE.
ALL RIGHT, VULCAN,
YOU MAY GO.
BUT YOU ARE
AN ENEMY ALIEN.
YOU WILL BE
UNDER OUR SCRUTINY
AT ALL TIMES.
IF I HAVE TO
WARN YOU...
NOT NECESSARY, COMMANDER.
I UNDERSTAND YOU...
VERY WELL.
RETURN TO YOUR COUNCIL,
BARONA.
YOU WILL RECEIVE OUR
OFFICIAL NOTIFICATIONS
AS SOON AS THEY
ARE PUBLISHED.
IN THE MEANTIME...
KEEP THE PEOPLE
IN ORDER.
IT IS
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY.
OR I WILL BE KILLED.
THAT IS EXACTLY RIGHT.
YOU WILL BE KILLED.
THAT MIND SIFTER
CAN'T BE ALL THE TERROR
THEY THINK IT IS.
IT SHOULD NOT BE
UNDERESTIMATED, CAPTAIN.
IT REACHES DIRECTLY
INTO THE MIND.
WE VULCANS HAVE
CERTAIN MENTAL--
CERTAIN DISCIPLINES
WHICH ENABLE ME TO
MAINTAIN A SHIELD.
WITHOUT THOSE DISCIPLINES,
THERE WOULD BE NO PROTECTION.
I'LL TRY
AND AVOID IT.
OUT OF THE WAY,
ORGANIAN.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
WE DID NOT NOTICE YOU.
NEXT TIME,
KEEP YOUR EYES OPEN,
OR I'LL SHUT THEM
PERMANENTLY.
CAPTAIN,
I STRONGLY SUGGEST
WE DIRECT OUR ENERGIES
TOWARD THE IMMEDIATE PROBLEM--
ACCOMPLISHING
OUR MISSION HERE.
YOU DIDN'T REALLY THINK
I WAS GOING TO
BEAT HIS HEAD IN,
DID YOU?
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
BUT AS YOU SAY,
WE STILL HAVE A JOB TO DO.
WE'LL RECEIVE NO HELP
FROM THE ORGANIANS.
MAYBE, BUT SOONER OR LATER,
THEY'RE GOING TO START RESENTING
HOW THE KLINGONS
RUN THINGS.
IF WE COULD PROVE
TO THEM...
THEY COULD DO SOMETHING
TO STRIKE BACK,
TO KEEP THE KLINGONS
OFF BALANCE.
VERBAL PERSUASION
SEEMS TO BE INEFFECTIVE.
PERHAPS A MORE
DIRECT APPROACH.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I HAD IN MIND.
MR. SPOCK, DID I
OR DID I NOT SEE SOMETHING
THAT LOOKED LIKE
A MUNITIONS DUMP
OUTSIDE
OF KOR'S HEADQUARTERS?
YOU DID.
I THINK IT'S TIME
WE DID A LITTLE
SIMPLE AND PLAIN
COMMUNICATING. TONIGHT.
A VERY MERITORIOUS IDEA,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE SHORT OF TOOLS.
I'M CERTAIN THE KLINGONS
WILL PROVIDE WHATEVER
IS NECESSARY.
IT'S A PLEASURE
DOING BUSINESS
WITH YOU, MR. SPOCK.
O.K. SO FAR.
SONIC GRENADE.
WITH A DELAYED-ACTION FUSE.
GOOD.
THESE CRATES CONTAIN
CHEMICAL EXPLOSIVES.
THEY SHOULD MAKE A MOST
SATISFACTORY DISPLAY.
6...5...4...3...
[EXPLOSION]
YOU WERE RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK.
A MOST SATISFACTORY
DISPLAY.
OF COURSE WE BLEW IT UP.
DELIBERATELY.
BUT THAT
WAS VIOLENCE.
WE DID IT TO SHOW YOU
THAT YOU COULD FIGHT BACK,
THAT YOU DON'T
HAVE TO BE SHEEP.
YOU CAN BE WOLVES.
TERRIBLE...
TO DESTROY.
HISTORY IS FULL
OF EXAMPLES
OF CIVIL POPULATIONS
FIGHTING BACK
SUCCESSFULLY
AGAINST A MILITARY
DICTATORSHIP.
WE MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO DESTROY THE KLINGONS,
BUT IF WE CAN TIE THEM UP,
BLOW UP THEIR INSTALLATIONS,
DISRUPT
THEIR COMMUNICATIONS,
MAKE ORGANIA
USELESS TO THEM--
OUR FLEET WILL
EVENTUALLY ARRIVE.
IN THE MEANTIME,
THE BATTLE IS OURS.
IT CAN BE
A SUCCESSFUL ONE.
CAPTAIN,
I IMPLORE YOU
NEVER TO DO
SUCH A THING AGAIN.
WHY? ARE YOU AFRAID
OF RETRIBUTION?
DOES YOUR PERSONAL FREEDOM
MEAN SO LITTLE TO YOU?
HOW LITTLE YOU
UNDERSTAND US, CAPTAIN.
ALL I UNDERSTAND IS THAT
YOU APPRENTLY DON'T HAVE
THE BACKBONE
TO STAND UP AND FIGHT
AND PROTECT
THE ONES YOU LOVE.
YOU SPEAK OF COURAGE,
GENTLEMEN.
DOES COURAGE
MEAN SO LITTLE TO YOU?
[FOOTSTEPS]
YOU SPEAK
OF COURAGE.
OBVIOUSLY
YOU DO NOT KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN COURAGE
AND FOOLHARDINESS.
ALWAYS IT IS
THE BRAVE ONES WHO DIE,
THE SOLDIERS.
I HOPE YOU WILL
CONTINUE TO SAVOR
THE SWEETNESS
OF YOUR LIFE.
YOU DISGUST ME.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO
DO WITH HIM, COMMANDER?
WHAT IS ALWAYS
DONE WITH SPIES
AND SABOTEURS.
HE WILL BE KILLED
AFTER HE HAS HAD
FIRST-HAND EXPERIENCE
OF OUR MIND SCANNER.
THERE'S NO NEED TO USE
YOUR MACHINE ON HIM, COMMANDER.
I CAN TELL YOU
HIS NAME.
IT IS CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK.
AYELBORNE.
WHAT?
CAPTAIN OF
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
A STARSHIP COMMANDER.
AND HIS FIRST OFFICER?
HMM.
I HAD HOPED TO MEET YOU
IN BATTLE, BUT...
FOR SOME REASON, HE FEELS THAT
HE MUST DESTROY YOU, COMMANDER,
JUST AS YOU FEEL
YOU MUST DESTROY HIM.
THAT'S GOING TO BE
RATHER DIFFICULT NOW.
ISN'T IT, CAPTAIN?
WHAT AN ADMIRABLE
PEOPLE.
DO YOU ALWAYS
BETRAY YOUR FRIENDS?
I DIDN'T WANT YOU
TO HARM HIM.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS FOR THE BEST.
NO HARM
WILL COME OF IT.
I'M USED TO
THE IDEA OF DYING.
BUT I HAVE
NO DESIRE TO DIE
FOR THE LIKES OF YOU.
I DON'T BLAME YOU,
CAPTAIN.
LOCK UP THE VULCAN.
TAKE THE CAPTAIN
TO MY OFFICE.
WE'LL HAVE A TALK
BEFORE I DO WHAT...
MUST BE DONE.
YOU'LL HAVE A DRINK
WITH ME, CAPTAIN?
NO, THANK YOU.
I ASSURE YOU
IT ISN'T DRUGGED.
WITH OUR MIND SCANNER,
WE HAVE NO NEED
FOR SUCH CRUDE METHODS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
OH, A VERY GREAT DEAL,
BUT FIRST
I WANT TO TALK.
JUST TALK.
YOU THINK
I'M GOING TO SIT HERE
AND JUST TALK
WITH THE ENEMY?
YOU'LL TALK.
EITHER HERE, NOW,
VOLUNTARILY,
OR UNDER
OUR MIND SCANNER.
THE FACT IS, CAPTAIN,
I HAVE
A GREAT ADMIRATION
FOR YOUR STARFLEET.
A REMARKABLE INSTRUMENT.
AND I MUST CONFESS
TO A CERTAIN
ADMIRATION FOR YOU.
I KNOW, OF COURSE,
THAT IT WAS YOU
WHO DESTROYED
OUR SUPPLIES LAST NIGHT.
SOMETHING WAS DESTROYED?
NOTHING INCONSEQUENTIAL,
I HOPE.
HA HA HA. HARDLY.
THEY WERE QUITE
IMPORTANT TO US,
BUT THEY CAN BE
REPLACED.
YOU OF THE FEDERATION,
YOU ARE MUCH LIKE US.
WE'RE NOTHING LIKE YOU.
WE'RE A DEMOCRATIC BODY.
COME NOW, CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT REFERRING
TO MINOR IDEOLOGICAL
DIFFERENCES.
I MEAN THAT WE ARE
SIMILAR AS A SPECIES.
HERE WE ARE,
ON A PLANET OF SHEEP,
TWO TIGERS,
PREDATORS, HUNTERS...
KILLERS,
AND IT IS PRECISELY THAT
WHICH MAKES US GREAT.
AND THERE IS A UNIVERSE
TO BE TAKEN.
IT'S A VERY LARGE
UNIVERSE, COMMANDER,
FULL OF PEOPLE WHO
DON'T LIKE THE KLINGONS.
EXCELLENT.
THEN IT SHALL BE
A MATTER OF TESTING
EACH OTHER'S WILLS.
OF POWER.
SURVIVAL MUST BE EARNED,
CAPTAIN.
TELL ME ABOUT THE DISPERSAL
OF YOUR STARFLEET.
GO CLIMB A TREE.
I CAN GET WHAT I WANT
THROUGH OUR MIND SCANNER,
BUT THERE WOULD BE VERY LITTLE
OF YOUR MIND LEFT, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE NO DESIRE
TO SEE YOU BECOME
A VEGETABLE.
THIS FRIEND OF YOURS,
THE VULCAN.
HE SEEMS TO HAVE
THE ABILITY
TO BLOCK OUR SCANNER.
I THINK PERHAPS
I WILL FIND OUT WHY.
I WILL HAVE HIM DISSECTED.
YOUR FRIEND KILLED.
YOU A MENTAL VEGETABLE.
NOT A PLEASANT
PROSPECT, CAPTAIN,
BUT IT LIES AHEAD FOR YOU
UNLESS YOU TELL ME
EVERYTHING I WANT TO KNOW.
12 HOURS, CAPTAIN.
IT WILL TAKE A LOT
LONGER THAN THAT,
COMMANDER.
LONGER THAN THAT
I WILL NOT WAIT.
I RESPECT YOU,
CAPTAIN, BUT...
THIS IS WAR,
A GAME WE KLINGONS
PLAY TO WIN.
TAKE HIM TO THE CELL
WITH HIS FRIEND.
AND WATCH HIM CLOSELY.
IT'S NO USE, JIM.
THERE'S NO WAY OUT.
HOW MUCH OF THE 12 HOURS
DO WE HAVE LEFT?
6 HOURS, 43 MINUTES,
IF THE KLINGONS
ARE PUNCTUAL.
I THINK WE CAN COUNT
ON THEM BEING PUNCTUAL.
BLOWING THAT MUNITIONS DUMP
WASN'T ENOUGH.
WE GET OUT OF HERE,
WE'VE GOT TO CARRY
THE ATTACK DIRECTLY TO KOR.
THESE ORGANIANS...
THEY DO NOT SEEM
TO UNDERSTAND.
MOST PECULIAR.
NEVERTHELESS,
OUR ORDERS STILL STAND.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE
SOME ATTEMPT
TO NEUTRALIZE
THE KLINGON OCCUPATION.
WE MAY NOT GET
THE CHANCE, CAPTAIN.
THESE WALLS
ARE VERY THICK.
AND THERE ARE GUARDS
EVERY FEW FEET DOWN THE HALL.
[BANGING]
OH, THERE YOU ARE,
GENTLEMEN.
I TRUST YOU ARE
IN GOOD HEALTH?
SHALL WE GO?
GO?
YES. YOUR CAPTORS PLANNED
TO DO VIOLENCE TO YOU.
THAT WE CANNOT PERMIT.
I CAME TO TAKE YOU AWAY.
YOU TURNED US OVER
TO THEM.
YOU EXPECT US
TO TRUST YOU NOW?
IS THERE REALLY
A CHOICE, CAPTAIN?
I OFFER YOU SAFETY.
WE CAN'T STAY HERE.
THIS IS THE FIRST PLACE
THEY'LL LOOK.
THEY WILL NOT COME HERE,
CAPTAIN. YOU MAY BELIEVE ME.
YOU TURN US IN,
THEN GET US OUT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING NOW,
WAITING FOR THE KLINGONS
TO POST A REWARD
SO YOU CAN TURN US IN AGAIN
AND COLLECT IT?
HOW LITTLE
YOU UNDERSTAND US,
CAPTAIN.
NOR DO WE UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED TO THE GUARDS
AT THE CITADEL.
PLEASE DO NOT
CONCERN YOURSELF
ABOUT THEM.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM?
WHY, NOTHING HAPPENED
TO THEM, CAPTAIN.
NOTHING AT ALL.
COMMANDER!
DON'T YOU SEE I'M BUSY?
THE TWO FEDERATION
PRISONERS--THEY'RE GONE.
YOU MEAN
THEY'VE ESCAPED?
I SWEAR,
NO ONE WAS AT FAULT.
THE GUARDS, 10 OF THEM,
WERE CONSTANTLY ON DUTY
WATCHING THE CELL.
THEN WHEN THEY OPENED IT
TO GIVE THEM FOOD,
THEY SIMPLY WEREN'T THERE.
AND THERE WAS NO WAY OUT.
IF YOU'RE LYING TO ME...
I SWEAR!
ALL RIGHT,
LIEUTENANT.
IMPLEMENT SPECIAL
OCCUPATION ORDER
NUMBER FOUR.
IMMEDIATELY!
SIR!
IS THAT ALL
YOU CAN DO, SMILE?
YOU ARE FREE, CAPTAIN.
I WANT TO KNOW
HOW I'M FREE AND WHY.
INDEED. THERE ARE
SOME QUESTIONS
I WOULD LIKE
TO ASK AS WELL.
THIS IDIOTIC
PLACIDITY OF YOURS,
YOUR REFUSAL TO DO ANYTHING
TO PROTECT YOURSELVES...
WE HAVE ALREADY
ANSWERED THAT QUESTION.
TO US, VIOLENCE
IS UNTHINKABLE.
[KOR] ATTENTION.
ATTENTION ALL ORGANIANS.
ATTENTION.
THIS IS COMMANDER KOR.
THE TWO FEDERATION
PRISONERS HAVE ESCAPED,
OBVIOUSLY WITH OUTSIDE AID.
THEY WILL BE RETURNED
IMMEDIATELY.
SO THAT YOU WILL KNOW
WE MEAN WHAT WE SAY...
LISTEN.
[PHASER WHIRRING]
THOSE ARE
KLINGON PHASERS.
TAKE THE DOOR.
GET DOWN, GENTLEMEN.
IN THE COURTYARD
OF MY HEADQUARTERS...
200 ORGANIANS
HAVE JUST BEEN KILLED.
200 OF THEM.
[KOR] IN 2 HOURS,
200 MORE WILL DIE
AND 200 MORE AFTER THAT
UNTIL THE TWO
FEDERATION SPIES
ARE TURNED OVER TO US.
THIS IS THE ORDER OF KOR.
DID YOU HEAR THEM?
YES, OF COURSE, CAPTAIN.
BUT NOTHING HAS CHANGED.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
IT SEEMS IT'S UP TO YOU AND ME.
IT WOULD
APPEAR SO, CAPTAIN.
THE FEDERATION HAS INVESTED
A GREAT DEAL OF MONEY
IN OUR TRAINING.
THEY'RE ABOUT DUE
FOR A SMALL RETURN.
WE HAVE 2 HOURS
WITH WHICH TO DO IT.
BUT ONLY 2.
MORE ORGANIANS
WILL DIE--
NO, MR. SPOCK. NO MORE
WILL DIE ON ACCOUNT OF US.
WHERE ARE THOSE PHASERS?
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
YOU'VE TOLD US A GREAT DEAL
ABOUT HOW YOU HATE VIOLENCE.
UNLESS YOU TELL ME
WHERE THOSE PHASERS ARE,
YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE MORE VIOLENCE
THAN YOU KNOW
WHAT TO DO WITH.
YOU MEAN YOU WOULD
ACTUALLY USE FORCE?
IT'S ENTIRELY
UP TO YOU.
AYELBORNE, THIS IS
OF NO MATTER.
PERHAPS
YOU'D BETTER LET HIM
HAVE WHAT HE WANTS.
VERY WELL. BUT IT WILL
DO YOU NO GOOD.
THEY'RE IN THAT CABINET.
GENTLEMEN, I HAVE
NO GREAT LOVE FOR YOU,
YOUR PLANET,
YOUR CULTURE.
DESPITE THAT,
MR. SPOCK AND I
ARE GOING TO GO OUT THERE
AND QUITE PROBABLY DIE
IN AN ATTEMPT TO SHOW YOU
THAT THERE ARE SOME THINGS
WORTH DYING FOR.
THERE ARE ONLY
TWO OF YOU
AGAINST AN ARMY.
DON'T YOU REALIZE
THAT WHAT YOU INTEND TO DO
WILL BE HOPELESS?
COME ON, MR. SPOCK,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
BRAVE MEN.
YES,
BUT SO FOOLISH.
INTERESTING, HOWEVER.
OF COURSE
WE CANNOT ALLOW IT.
TO STOP THEM
IS VERY BAD.
IT IS NECESSARY.
THEY MAY HARM ONE ANOTHER.
TREFAYNE.
THEY WILL WAIT
UNTIL DARKNESS.
AND THEN?
TERRIBLE,
INCONCEIVABLE,
SAVAGE.
[SIGHS]
WE WILL WAIT.
[DOG BARKING]
MR. SPOCK, CAN WE
GET THOSE 2 GUARDS?
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
THE ODDS ARE
ON OUR GETTING
OUT OF HERE?
DIFFICULT TO BE
PRECISE, CAPTAIN.
I SHOULD SAY
APPROXIMATELY
7,824.7 TO ONE.
DIFFICULT TO BE PRECISE?
7,824 TO ONE?
7,824.7 TO ONE.
THAT'S A PRETTY CLOSE
APPROXIMATION.
I ENDEAVOR
TO BE ACCURATE.
YOU DO QUITE WELL.
SET YOUR PHASER ON STUN.
WE'RE AFTER THE TOP DOG,
NOT THE MEMBERS
OF THE PACK.
VERY GOOD.
BUT IF THE SITUATION
CALLS FOR IT,
WE KILL.
IS THAT CLEAR?
CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
I'LL TAKE THE ONE
ON THE LEFT.
FIRE.
IT HAS BEGUN.
VERY WELL.
IT WILL BE HARD.
PREPARE YOURSELVES.
NO RESULTS, COMMANDER.
NOTHING?
I CANNOT UNDERSTAND
THESE PEOPLE.
THEY KNOW WHAT
DEATH IS, DON'T THEY?
THEY DO NOT SEEM TO BE
WORRIED ABOUT ANYTHING.
BAD ENOUGH TO BE
A MILITARY GOVERNOR,
BUT TO GOVERN
A POPULATION OF SHEEP?
VERY WELL, LIEUTENANT.
ROUND UP 200 MORE.
YES, SIR.
FOOLS! WILL I HAVE TO
KILL THEM ALL?
IF YOU DON'T TELL ME
WHAT I WANT TO KNOW,
I'LL KILL YOU
HERE AND NOW,
IS THAT CLEAR?
YES, THAT'S CLEAR.
IS KOR'S OFFICE
DOWN THERE?
YES.
WHAT ABOUT
THE HOSTAGES?
TALK.
I AM TO GATHER
200 MORE.
TO BE KILLED?
YES.
MR. SPOCK.
UH!
WELL, WHAT ARE
THE ODDS NOW?
LESS THAN 7,000-TO-1,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S REMARKABLE
WE'VE GOTTEN THIS FAR.
LESS THAN 7,000-TO-1.
WELL...GETTING BETTER.
GETTING BETTER.
JUST STAY
WHERE YOU ARE,
COMMANDER.
YOU HAVE DONE WELL
TO GET THIS FAR
THROUGH MY GUARDS.
I BELIEVE YOU'LL FIND
THAT SEVERAL OF THEM
ARE NO LONGER IN PERFECT
OPERATING CONDITION.
SO...
YOU ARE HERE.
YOU WILL BE INTERESTED
IN KNOWING
THAT A FEDERATION FLEET
IS ON ITS WAY HERE
AT THE MOMENT.
OUR FLEET IS PREPARING
TO MEET THEM.
CHECKMATE, COMMANDER.
SHALL WE WAIT AND SEE
THE RESULTS
BEFORE YOU, UH...
KILL ME?
I DON'T INTEND
TO KILL YOU
UNLESS I HAVE TO.
AH, SENTIMENTALITY...
MERCY...
THE EMOTIONS OF PEACE...
YOUR WEAKNESS,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
THE KLINGON EMPIRE
SHALL WIN.
THINK OF IT,
AS WE SIT HERE,
IN SPACE ABOVE US,
THE DESTINY OF THE GALAXY
WILL BE DECIDED
FOR THE NEXT 10,000 YEARS.
CAN I OFFER YOU A DRINK?
WE CAN TOAST THE VICTORY
OF THE KLINGON FLEET.
YOU MAY BE PREMATURE.
THERE ARE
MANY POSSIBILITIES.
TODAY WE CONQUER.
THOUGH IF SOMEDAY
WE ARE DEFEATED,
WELL, WAR HAS
ITS FORTUNES,
GOOD AND BAD.
DO YOU KNOW WHY
WE ARE SO STRONG?
BECAUSE WE ARE A UNIT.
EACH OF US IS PART
OF THE GREATER WHOLE,
ALWAYS
UNDER SURVEILLANCE.
EVEN A COMMANDER
LIKE MYSELF.
ALWAYS UNDER SURVEILLANCE,
CAPTAIN.
IF YOU WILL NOTE.
COVER, SPOCK! BACK!
SHOOT! SHOOT!
OH!
AAH!
WHAT IS IT, SPOCK?
INEXPLICABLE, CAPTAIN.
EXTREME HEAT.
NOT ONLY THE WEAPONS,
BUT THE BODIES AS WELL.
AAH!
WE ARE TERRIBLY SORRY
TO BE FORCED TO INTERFERE,
GENTLEMEN,
BUT WE CANNOT PERMIT YOU
TO HARM YOURSELVES.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WE HAVE PUT A STOP
TO YOUR VIOLENCE.
YOU...ARE STOPPING THIS?
YOU?
ALL INSTRUMENTS
OF VIOLENCE
ON THIS PLANET
NOW RADIATE
A TEMPERATURE
OF 350 DEGREES.
THEY ARE
INOPERATIVE.
MY FLEET!
THE SAME CONDITIONS EXIST
ON BOTH STARFLEETS.
THERE WILL BE NO BATTLE.
RIDICULOUS!
I SUGGEST YOU
CONTACT THEM.
YOU, TOO, CAPTAIN.
YOUR SHIP IS NOW
WITHIN RANGE OF YOUR
COMMUNICATIONS DEVICE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
[SULU] CAPTAIN...
I--I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
WE WERE JUST CLOSING IN
ON THE KLINGON FLEET
WHEN EVERY CONTROL
ON OUR SHIP
BECAME TOO HOT
TO HANDLE.
OUR POWER IS GONE.
OUR PHASER BANKS
ARE DEAD.
STAND BY, SULU.
MY FLEET...
IT'S HELPLESS.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
AS I STAND HERE,
I ALSO STAND UPON
THE HOME PLANET
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE
AND THE HOME PLANET
OF YOUR FEDERATION, CAPTAIN.
I'M GOING TO PUT A STOP
TO THIS INSANE WAR.
YOU'RE WHAT?
YOU'RE TALKING NONSENSE.
IT IS BEING DONE.
YOU CAN'T JUST
STOP THE FLEET.
WHAT GIVES YOU
THE RIGHT?
YOU CAN'T INTERFERE.
WHAT HAPPENS IN SPACE
IS NOT YOUR BUSINESS.
UNLESS BOTH SIDES AGREE
TO AN IMMEDIATE CESSATION
OF HOSTILITIES,
ALL YOUR ARMED FORCES,
WHEREVER THEY MAY BE,
WILL BE IMMEDIATELY
IMMOBILIZED.
WE HAVE LEGITIMATE
GRIEVANCES AGAINST
THE KLINGONS.
THEY'VE INVADED
OUR TERRITORY,
KILLED OUR CITIZENS.
THEY'RE OPENLY
AGGRESSIVE.
THEY'VE BOASTED
THAT THEY'LL
TAKE OVER HALF
THE GALAXY.
AND WHY NOT?
WE'RE THE STRONGER!
YOU'VE TRIED
TO HEM US IN,
CUT OFF VITAL SUPPLIES,
STRANGLED OUR TRADE!
YOU'VE BEEN ASKING
FOR WAR!
YOU'RE THE ONES WHO
ISSUED THE ULTIMATUM
TO WITHDRAW FROM
THE DISPUTED AREAS!
THEY'RE NOT DISPUTED!
THEY'RE CLEARLY OURS!
AND NOW YOU STEP IN
WITH SOME KIND OF TRICK.
IT IS NO TRICK,
COMMANDER.
WE HAVE SIMPLY
PUT AN END TO YOUR WAR.
ALL YOUR MILITARY FORCES,
WHEREVER THEY ARE,
ARE NOW COMPLETELY
PARALYZED.
WE FIND INTERFERENCE
IN OTHER PEOPLE'S
AFFAIRS
MOST DISGUSTING,
BUT YOU GENTLEMEN HAVE
GIVEN US NO CHOICE.
YOU SHOULD BE
THE FIRST TO BE
ON OUR SIDE.
200 HOSTAGES KILLED.
NO ONE HAS BEEN
KILLED, CAPTAIN.
NO ONE HAS DIED HERE
IN UNCOUNTED THOUSANDS
OF YEARS.
YOU ARE LIARS.
YOU ARE MEDDLING
IN THINGS
THAT ARE NONE
OF YOUR BUSINESS.
EVEN IF YOU
HAVE SOME...
POWER THAT WE DON'T
UNDERSTAND...
YOU HAVE
NO RIGHT TO DICTATE
TO OUR FEDERATION--
OR OUR EMPIRE!
HOW TO HANDLE
OUR INTERSTELLAR
RELATIONS!
WE HAVE THE RIGHT--
TO WAGE WAR, CAPTAIN?
TO KILL MILLIONS
OF INNOCENT PEOPLE?
TO DESTROY LIFE
ON A PLANETARY SCALE?
IS THAT WHAT
YOU'RE DEFENDING?
WELL, NO ONE
WANTS WAR...
BUT THERE ARE
PROPER CHANNELS.
PEOPLE HAVE
A RIGHT TO HANDLE
THEIR OWN AFFAIRS.
EVENTUALLY,
WE WILL...
OH, EVENTUALLY,
YOU WILL HAVE PEACE,
BUT ONLY AFTER MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE HAVE DIED.
IT IS TRUE THAT
IN THE FUTURE,
YOU AND THE KLINGONS
WILL BECOME FAST FRIENDS.
YOU WILL WORK TOGETHER.
NEVER!
YOUR EMOTIONS
ARE MOST DISCORDANT.
WE DO NOT WISH
TO SEEM INHOSPITABLE,
BUT, GENTLEMEN,
YOU MUST LEAVE.
YES.
PLEASE LEAVE US.
THE MERE PRESENCE
OF BEINGS LIKE YOURSELVES
IS INTENSELY
PAINFUL TO US.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
"BEINGS
LIKE YOURSELVES?"
MILLIONS OF YEARS AGO,
CAPTAIN...
WE WERE HUMANOID,
LIKE YOURSELVES,
BUT WE HAVE DEVELOPED
BEYOND THE NEED
OF PHYSICAL BODIES.
THAT OF US WHICH YOU SEE
IS MERE APPEARANCE...
FOR YOUR SAKE.
CAPTAIN, IT'S A TRICK.
WE CAN HANDLE THEM.
I HAVE AN ARMY.
FASCINATING.
PURE ENERGY...
PURE THOUGHT...
TOTALLY INCORPOREAL...
NOT LIFE
AS WE KNOW IT AT ALL.
BUT WHAT ABOUT
THIS PLANET?
THE FIELDS,
THE BUILDINGS,
THIS CITADEL?
CONVENTIONALIZATIONS,
I SHOULD SAY...
USELESS TO THE ORGANIANS,
CREATED SO THAT VISITORS,
SUCH AS OURSELVES,
COULD HAVE CONVENTIONAL
POINTS OF REFERENCE.
BUT IS ALL OF THIS
POSSIBLE?
WE HAVE SEEN IT
WITH OUR OWN EYES.
I SHOULD SAY THE ORGANIANS
ARE AS FAR ABOVE US
ON THE EVOLUTIONARY
SCALE...
AS WE ARE ABOVE
THE AMOEBA.
WELL, COMMANDER, I GUESS
THAT TAKES CARE OF THE WAR.
OBVIOUSLY, THE ORGANIANS
AREN'T GOING TO LET US FIGHT.
A SHAME, CAPTAIN.
IT WOULD HAVE
BEEN GLORIOUS.
YOU'VE BEEN
MOST RESTRAINED
SINCE WE LEFT ORGANIA.
I'M EMBARRASSED.
I WAS FURIOUS
WITH THE ORGANIANS
FOR STOPPING A WAR
I DIDN'T WANT.
WE THINK OF OURSELVES
AS THE MOST POWERFUL
BEINGS IN THE UNIVERSE.
IT'S UNSETTLING
TO DISCOVER
THAT WE'RE WRONG.
CAPTAIN...
IT TOOK MILLIONS OF YEARS
FOR THE ORGANIANS
TO EVOLVE
INTO WHAT THEY ARE.
EVEN THE GODS DID NOT
SPRING INTO BEING OVERNIGHT.
YOU AND I HAVE NO REASON
TO BE EMBARRASSED.
WE DID, AFTER ALL,
BEAT THE ODDS.
OH, NO, NO, NO,
MR. SPOCK,
WE DIDN'T BEAT THE ODDS.
WE DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE.
THE ORGANIANS
RAIDED THE GAME.