WELL, MR. SPOCK?
VERY TYPICAL, CAPTAIN.
IRON-SILICON BASE,
OXYGEN-HYDROGEN ATMOSPHERE,
LARGELY ARID,
NO DISCERNIBLE LIFE.
NO SURPRISES.
CARTOGRAPHIC SECTION,
BEGIN SCANNING.
TIE INDIVIDUAL SECTION
988-TG, COMPUTER BANK 22.
KIRK OUT.
ABOUT FOUR MORE ORBITS
OUGHT TO DO IT, MR. LESLEY.
THEN WE'LL WRAP IT UP.
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR STARBASE 200.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN!
MR. SPOCK.
INCREDIBLE, CAPTAIN.
WHAT WAS THAT?
WHAT MY INSTRUMENTS READ
IS TOTALLY UNBELIEVABLE,
CAPTAIN.
TWICE,
FOR A SPLIT SECOND
EACH TIME,
EVERYTHING WITHIN RANGE
OF OUR INSTRUMENTS
SEEMED ON THE VERGE
OF WINKING OUT.
I WANT FACTS,
NOT POETRY.
I HAVE GIVEN YOU
THE FACTS, CAPTAIN.
THE ENTIRE
MAGNETIC FIELD
IN THIS SOLAR SYSTEM
SIMPLY BLINKED.
THE PLANET BELOW,
THE MASS OF WHICH
WE'RE MEASURING,
ATTAINED ZERO GRAVITY.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WHAT YOU'RE DESCRIBING...
IS NONEXISTENCE.
STANDARD GENERAL ALERT
SIGNAL FROM STARFLEET
COMMAND, CAPTAIN.
ALL STATIONS TO IMMEDIATE
ALERT STATUS. STAND BY.
CAPTAIN, SCANNERS NOW
REPORT A LIFE OBJECT
ON THE PLANET'S
SURFACE BELOW.
YOU JUST DID A
COMPLETE LIFE SURVEY
5 MINUTES AGO.
HOW IS IT
YOU'RE JUST
PICKING IT UP NOW?
INEXPLICABLE, CAPTAIN.
THIS READING BEGAN
AT APPROXIMATELY THE MOMENT
THAT THE PULSATION PHENOMENON
BEGAN TO SUBSIDE.
WELL, WHAT IS IT,
THIS OBJECT?
ITS PHYSICAL MAKEUP?
A LIVING BEING.
BODY TEMPERATURE
98.5 FAHRENHEIT.
MASS, ELECTRICAL IMPULSES,
MOVEMENT.
IT IS APPARENTLY HUMAN,
CAPTAIN.
AND ITS APPEARANCE
COINCIDED WITH THIS
COSMIC WINKING OUT?
ALMOST TO THE SECOND.
EXPLANATION?
NONE.
SPECULATION.
COULD THIS BEING
PRESENT ANY DANGER
TO THE SHIP?
POSSIBLE.
VERY POSSIBLE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
NOTIFY SECURITY
TO HAVE AN ARMED
DETACHMENT OF MEN
READY TO BEAM
DOWN WITH US.
LET'S GO.
ANY WORD COMES THROUGH
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND,
PIPE IT DOWN
IMMEDIATELY.
COMMUNICATIONS,
PRIORITY ONE.
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3087.6.
WHILE INVESTIGATING
AN UNCHARTED PLANET,
THE ENTERPRISE AND
AT LEAST THIS ENTIRE
QUADRANT OF SPACE
HAS BEEN SUBJECTED TO VIOLENT,
UNEXPLAINED STRESS AND FORCE.
SENSORS HAVE REPORTED THE
PRESENCE OF A HUMAN BEING
ON THE PLANET BELOW
WHO MIGHT BE CONNECTED
WITH THE PHENOMENON.
WITH MY FIRST OFFICER
AND A SECURITY TEAM,
I HAVE SET OUT
IN SEARCH OF HIM.
YOU CAME!
THANK THE HEAVENS.
THERE'S STILL TIME.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
WE CAN STILL STOP HIM.
BUT I--BUT I...
NEED...NEED YOUR HELP.
AAH!
NOTHING YET, SIR.
REPORT ON THE DILITHIUM
CRYSTALS, CAPTAIN.
YES.
WHATEVER
THAT PHENOMENON WAS,
IT DRAINED ALMOST ALL OF
OUR CRYSTALS COMPLETELY.
IT COULD MEAN TROUBLE.
YOU HAVE A TALENT
FOR UNDERSTATEMENT,
LIEUTENANT.
WITHOUT FULL CRYSTAL POWER,
OUR ORBIT WILL BEGIN
TO DECAY IN 10 HOURS.
RE-AMPLIFY IMMEDIATELY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
ANY FURTHER MAGNETIC
DISTURBANCE?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
SCANNERS INDICATE
SITUATION NORMAL.
NOTHING?
NOTHING.
ILLOGICAL.
AN EFFECT OF SUCH
PROPORTIONS, UNEXPLAINABLE
BY ANY ESTABLISHED
PHYSICAL LAWS THAT
I'M AWARE OF.
I HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
ASCERTAIN ONE FACT.
THOUGH THE EFFECT,
WHATEVER IT WAS,
WAS UNQUESTIONABLY
WIDESPREAD, IT WAS
STRONGEST HERE,
ON THE PLANET
BENEATH US.
KEEP CHECKING.
RED 2 MESSAGE
IN ONE MINUTE, CAPTAIN.
STARFLEET COMMAND.
CODE FACTOR 1, SIR.
REPEAT.
CODE FACTOR 1.
INVASION STATUS.
ALL HANDS, THIS
IS THE CAPTAIN.
BATTLE STATIONS.
I REPEAT, BATTLE
STATIONS.
THIS IS NO DRILL.
[INTERCOM BUZZER]
McCOY, CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
ABOUT OUR PATIENT--
YES, DOCTOR, QUICKLY.
HE'LL MAKE IT.
HE'LL BE STIFF AND
SORE FOR A WHILE,
BUT HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'LL TALK TO HIM
LATER, THANK YOU.
KIRK OUT.
MESSAGE READY, CAPTAIN.
MAIN SCREEN,
COMING UP.
KIRK HERE.
ENTERPRISE STANDING
BY, COMMODORE.
YOU'RE AWARE OF THE EFFECT
AN HOUR AGO?
YES, SIR.
YOU MAY NOT BE
AWARE OF ITS SCOPE.
IT OCCURRED IN EVERY QUADRANT
OF THE GALAXY AND FAR BEYOND.
COMPLETE DISRUPTION
OF NORMAL MAGNETIC
AND GRAVIMETRIC FIELDS,
TIME WARP DISTORTION,
POSSIBLE RADIATION
VARIATIONS...
AND ALL OF THEM CENTERING
IN THE GENERAL AREA
WHICH YOU ARE
NOW PATROLLING.
THE QUESTION IS,
ARE THESE NATURAL PHENOMENA...
OR ARE THEY
MECHANICALLY CREATED?
AND IF THEY ARE,
BY WHOM, FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
YOUR GUESS, CAPTAIN?
THANK YOU, SIR.
I HAVE CONSIDERED
ALL THE ALTERNATIVES.
MY BEST GUESS
IS IT COULD BE A
PRELUDE TO INVASION.
EXACTLY OUR CONSENSUS.
I'M GIVING YOU THE JOB
OF FINDING OUT SPECIFICALLY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAN YOU ASSIGN ME
OTHER STARSHIPS
AS A RESERVE?
NEGATIVE. I'M EVACUATING
ALL STARFLEET UNITS
AND PERSONNEL
WITHIN 100 PARSECS
OF YOUR POSITION.
IT'S GOING TO BE TOUGH
ON YOU AND THE ENTERPRISE,
BUT THAT'S THE JOB
YOU'VE DRAWN.
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
I SEE.
YOU MEAN...
WE'RE THE BAIT.
GOOD LUCK.
THANK YOU, SIR.
MAINTAIN ALERT STATUS
AT ALL BATTLE STATIONS.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
FROM THE TOP,
MR. SPOCK.
FIRST, PHENOMENON CAME
FROM THE PLANET BELOW.
SECONDLY, THE DANGER IS
APPARENTLY REAL
AND IMMINENT.
THIRD, A CLOSER EXAMINATION
OF THE PLANET'S SURFACE
WOULD BE IN ORDER.
MY JOB, SIR?
YES.
MEANWHILE, I'LL TALK
TO OUR UNEXPECTED GUEST.
MAYBE HE CAN PROVIDE
SOME ANSWERS.
THAT'S HOW I CAME TO BE
DOWN THERE, CAPTAIN,
PURSUING THE DEVIL'S
OWN SPAWN--
A THING I'VE CHASED
ACROSS THE UNIVERSE.
HE'S HUMANOID, OUTSIDE,
BUT INSIDE,
HE'S A HIDEOUS,
MURDERING MONSTER.
I'LL GET HIM, CAPTAIN.
I SWEAR IT.
YOU SAY THIS ONE MAN--
NOT MAN!
THING.
THING...DESTROYED
YOUR ENTIRE CIVILIZATION.
TO THE LAST MAN,
WOMAN, AND CHILD.
HOW DID YOU ESCAPE?
I WAS INSPECTING
MAGNETIC COMMUNICATIONS
SATELLITES.
YOU BELIEVE ME,
DON'T YOU?
BEFORE WE PICKED YOU UP,
OUR SHIP SUSTAINED A NUMBER
OF INCREDIBLE EFFECTS.
THAT WAS HE!
HE'S DEATH...ANTILIFE.
HE LIVES TO DESTROY!
IS HE THE THING
THAT ATTACKED YOU?
YES.
I GIVE YOU MY WORD.
I SWEAR IT.
WE DON'T HAVE
ANY OTHER FACTS,
ANY INFORMATION.
THEN YOU'LL JOIN ME
IN MY HOLY CAUSE.
HELP ME
IN VISITING JUSTICE
AND VENGEANCE UPON HIM?
MY ONLY CAUSE IS
THE SAFETY OF MY SHIP
AND THE MISSION WE'RE ON.
YOU'LL BEAM DOWN
WITH ME.
I'LL CHECK YOUR STORY OUT.
SPOCK,
FIND ANYTHING?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
ANYTHING FROM OUR GUEST?
ACCORDING TO HIM,
THERE'S A CREATURE
OF SOME SORT DOWN HERE,
A HUMANOID.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
COMMUNICATED THAT INFORMATION.
I ORDERED RECONFIRMATION
ON OUR SENSORS.
THEY INDICATE NO LIVING
CREATURE ON THIS PLANET.
I SUGGEST, CAPTAIN,
THAT YOU'VE BEEN LIED TO.
CAPTAIN, YOU YOURSELF SAID
THERE WERE NO OTHER
EXPLANATIONS.
WHY DO YOU GIVE
CREDENCE TO THIS MAN?
I FAIL TO COMPREHEND
YOUR INDIGNATION, SIR.
I HAVE SIMPLY MADE
THE LOGICAL DEDUCTION
THAT YOU ARE A LIAR.
LET'S HAVE IT.
THE TRUTH THIS TIME.
OH!
YOU'VE COME BACK
HERE, LIZARD.
WELL, DON'T STOP.
HERE I AM.
COME AT ME AGAIN.
WE'LL FINISH IT!
CAN YOU IDENTIFY THAT?
I'M TRYING, CAPTAIN.
LAZARUS!
YOU STAY HERE.
ALL PERSONNEL,
SECURITY RED.
YOU CAN'T RUN!
IT'LL DO YOU NO GOOD!
I'LL CHASE YOU TO THE
VERY FIRES OF HELL!
LAZARUS,
WHAT HAPPENED?
I SAW IT AGAIN,
THE THING.
IT ATTACKED ME.
I'LL HELP YOU
GET OUT OF HERE.
CAPTAIN, READINGS
OF THE EFFECT INDICATE
IT'S CENTERED HERE
ON THIS PLANET,
ALMOST ON
THIS VERY SPOT.
I TOLD YOU
IT WAS THE THING--
ALL WHITE, BLACK...
AND EMPTY,
A TERRIBLE EMPTINESS.
LET'S GET BACK
TO THE SHIP.
HE'LL KILL US ALL
IF WE DON'T
KILL HIM FIRST!
KILL! KILL!
KILL! KILL! KILL!
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3088.3.
WE CONTINUE TO ORBIT
THE DEAD PLANET,
WHICH SEEMS TO BE THE SOURCE
OF THE PHENOMENON
WHICH HAS STRUCK
THE ENTERPRISE
AND ALL SECTIONS
OF THE GALAXY ONCE AGAIN.
AS FOR LAZARUS,
THE STORY HE TELLS ME
ABOUT THE HUMANOID
CONTINUES TO TROUBLE ME.
ANY LUCK?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
I CAN NO MORE EXPLAIN
THE OCCURRENCE OF
THE SECOND PHENOMENON
THAN I CAN THE FIRST.
WHAT IF THERE'S
A SHRED OF TRUTH
TO WHAT LAZARUS SAID?
THAT A SINGLE CREATURE,
A HUMANOID
COULD BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR AN EFFECT
OF SUCH MAGNITUDE?
HARD TO BELIEVE.
INDEED.
BUT THE REST
OF HIS STORY
SEEMS TO FIT.
HIS WOUNDS TESTIFY
TO AN APPARENT
CONFRONTATION
WITH SOMETHING.
AFFIRMATIVE.
ASSUMING THERE IS
A HUMANOID--SOMETHING--
HOW DOES HE DO IT?
HE HAS NO
WEAPONS, NO POWERS.
CAPTAIN, I ONLY
KNOW FOR CERTAIN
THAT THE OCCURRENCE
OF THE PHENOMENON
COINCIDES EXACTLY
WITH THE MOMENTS
THAT LAZARUS HAS
HIS ALLEGED CONFRONTATIONS.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
DR. McCOY
ASKING TO SEE YOU
IN SICK BAY, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T KNOW, JIM.
MAYBE
I'M IMAGINING THINGS,
AND MAYBE I'M NOT.
YOU TELL ME.
THAT'S WHY YOU
BROUGHT ME DOWN HERE.
WELL, AS YOU KNOW,
WE BOTH BROUGHT
LAZARUS IN HERE.
AND I TREATED A DEEP ABRASION
ON HIS FOREHEAD, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
AND THEN I BANDAGED IT,
I STEPPED INTO THIS ROOM
FOR JUST A MOMENT--
BONES, I HAVE A LOT
OF THINGS TO DO.
GET TO THE POINT.
WELL, SAY HE'S GOT
THE CONSTITUTION
OF A DINOSAUR,
RECUPERATIVE POWERS,
DITTO.
AND AS WE BOTH KNOW,
I'M A BRIGHT YOUNG MEDIC
WITH A MIRACULOUS TOUCH.
WELL, WHY, THEN,
WHEN I RETURNED,
THERE WASN'T
A TRACE OF THAT WOUND
ON HIS FOREHEAD?
NOT EVEN A BRUISE.
IT WAS LIKE HE HAD
NEVER BEEN INJURED.
WHERE IS HE?
I DON'T KNOW, JIM.
THIS IS A BIG SHIP.
I'M JUST
A COUNTRY DOCTOR.
HI.
HI. COFFEE?
OH. IS THAT AN
ORDER, LIEUTENANT?
I KNOW
WHAT YOU MEAN.
THE AMPLIFICATION
FINISHED ON THE
DILITHIUM CRYSTALS?
YEAH, READY AND WAITING.
LAZARUS,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
UH, YES, SIR...
BUT IMPATIENT.
HAVE YOU DECIDED
TO HELP ME YET?
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
NO. I HAVE
A SHIP'S PHYSICIAN
WITH A STRANGE
SENSE OF HUMOR.
NO, BUT THIS IS NO
JOKE, JIM. I KNOW
WHAT I SAW.
[UHURA]
BRIDGE CALLING THE CAPTAIN.
GO.
[SPOCK] REQUEST YOU
COME TO THE BRIDGE,
CAPTAIN.
FIND SOMETHING?
SOMETHING
QUITE EXTRAORDINARY.
ON MY WAY.
LAZARUS,
YOU'RE WITH ME.
BONES, IF I HAD
TIME, I'D LAUGH.
MAIN SCREEN ON,
LIEUTENANT.
SCREEN ON, SIR.
A SOURCE OF RADIATION,
CAPTAIN.
HOW IS IT THE SCANNERS
DIDN'T PICK IT UP BEFORE?
BECAUSE
IT IS NOT THERE.
ANOTHER RIDDLE?
FIRST DR. McCOY,
THEN YOU?
WHAT I MEAN,
CAPTAIN, IS THAT
ACCORDING TO OUR USUAL
SCANNING PROCEDURES,
THERE'S NOTHING THERE
THAT COULD BE CAUSING
THAT EFFECT.
BUT IT IS THERE.
AFFIRMATIVE.
I CONFESS I AM SOMEWHAT
AT A LOSS FOR WORDS.
IT MAY BE DESCRIBED,
THOUGH LOOSELY
AND INACCURATELY,
AS A...RIP
IN OUR UNIVERSE.
WHAT?
A KIND OF PHYSICAL
WARP, CAPTAIN,
IN WHICH NONE OF
OUR ESTABLISHED
PHYSICAL LAWS
APPLY WITH
ANY REGULARITY.
HOWEVER, WITH
THE DILITHIUM CRYSTALS,
I WAS ABLE
TO LOCALIZE IT.
YES!
THAT'S IT!
THE DILITHIUM CRYSTALS.
THEIR POWER...
WE COULD DO IT.
YOU REFER
TO THE HUMANOID?
YES. WE'VE GOT HIM,
CAPTAIN, WE'VE GOT HIM.
WHAT DO THE CRYSTALS
HAVE TO DO WITH IT?
ALL THEY SHOW IS A
POINT OF RADIATION.
THAT'S JUST IT.
THAT'S THE KEY.
THAT'S THE WAY
TO TRAP HIM.
THAT'S THE SOLUTION.
CAPTAIN...
I BEG OF YOU.
I PLEAD.
I DEMAND.
GIVE ME THE CRYSTALS.
OUT OF
THE QUESTION.
THOSE CRYSTALS ARE
THE VERY HEART OF
THE POWER MY SHIP.
YOU FOOL.
THERE WON'T BE ANY SHIP
IF WE DON'T KILL HIM.
HE'LL DESTROY YOU ALL.
HOW?
NOW, YOU TELL ME HOW!
ALL I'VE HEARD FROM
YOU IS DOUBLE-TALK,
LIES, THREATS,
ACCUSATIONS
THAT DON'T HOLD
AN OUNCE OF WATER.
NOW, YOU TELL ME,
HOW DOES IT PRESENT
A DANGER TO MY SHIP?
I WARN YOU,
CAPTAIN.
YOU'LL GIVE ME
THE CRYSTALS.
DON'T THREATEN
ME, LAZARUS.
NO THREAT INTENDED.
CAPTAIN...
I'LL HAVE MY VENGEANCE.
LIEUTENANT MASTERS,
CAPTAIN'S CALLING.
MASTERS HERE.
[KIRK]
LIEUTENANT, CAN YOU
PREPARE AN EXPERIMENTATION
CHAMBER IN 10 MINUTES?
ALL DILITHIUM
CRYSTALS FULL POWER.
I'LL CHECK, SIR.
CAPTAIN, THE CHAMBER
WILL BE READY IN
10 MINUTES, SIR.
MY ASSISTANT AND I WILL--
CAPTAIN!
LIEUTENANT, WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S WRONG?
LIEUTENANT? LIEUTENANT?
CAPTAIN,
SECURITY REPORTS
LAZARUS MISSING.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3088.7.
WE ARE NO CLOSER
TO FINDING AN ANSWER
TO THE STRANGE PHENOMENON
THAN WE WERE
AT THE BEGINNING.
NOT ONLY HAVE TWO OF MY
CREWMEN BEEN ATTACKED,
TWO OF OUR DILITHIUM
CRYSTALS ARE MISSING,
AND WITHOUT THEM,
THE ENTERPRISE CANNOT
OPERATE AT FULL POWER.
THEY MUST BE FOUND.
FACT--YOU SAID YOU
NEEDED THE CRYSTALS.
FACT--AN HOUR AFTER YOU
SAID YOU MUST HAVE THEM,
THEY WERE MISSING.
FACT--TWO OF MY CREWMEN
WERE ATTACKED.
AND FACT, CAPTAIN--
I DIDN'T TAKE THE CRYSTALS.
I'M NOT THE ONE.
FIND MY ENEMY.
FIND THE BEAST,
AND YOU'LL
FIND THE CRYSTALS.
HOW DID THIS BEAST
GET ABOARD MY SHIP?
HE DID.
ISN'T THAT ENOUGH?
NO. HE DIDN'T
TRANSPORT UP.
A REPORT WOULD
HAVE BEEN MADE.
I TELL YOU, WE'RE
DEALING WITH A CREATURE
CAPABLE OF
DESTROYING WORLDS.
WHY DOES HE
NEED THE CRYSTALS?
FOR WHAT REASON?
FOR THE SAME REASON
THAT I DO.
LISTEN TO ME.
HE'S HUMANOID.
WHY, HE...
HE CAN PILOT
A SPACESHIP.
HE CAN COMPUTE FORMULAS
TO DESTROY RACES.
HE CAN STEAL AN ENERGY
SOURCE FOR HIS VEHICLE
SO HE CAN ESCAPE FROM ME.
ARE YOU DEAF
AS WELL AS BLIND?
SIT DOWN.
THE CRYSTALS
CERTAINLY AREN'T HERE.
THERE'S AN UNEXPLAINED
RADIATION SOURCE
ON THE PLANET.
OBVIOUSLY
SOME CONNECTION.
WE'LL CHECK IT OUT.
ORGANIZE A SEARCH PARTY
IMMEDIATELY.
MR. LAZARUS WILL
BEAM DOWN WITH US.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOU MAY NOT HAVE
REASON TO THANK ME,
DEPENDING ON
WHAT WE FIND.
WHAT DO YOU BELIEVE NOW,
CAPTAIN?
I BELIEVE
THE MISSING CRYSTALS
AREN'T IN YOUR SHIP.
MR. SPOCK?
UNABLE TO LOCATE
THE SOURCE OF RADIATION.
WHY NOT? YOU HAD IT
SPOTTED FROM THE ENTERPRISE.
IT HAS SIMPLY
DISAPPEARED, CAPTAIN.
I WANT EVERY INCH OF
THIS TERRAIN CHECKED.
LOOK FOR FOOTPRINT,
MOVEMENT--ANYTHING.
CALL OUT IF YOU
SPOT ANYTHING.
DON'T BE AFRAID
TO USE YOUR WEAPONS.
[THUNDER]
[THUNDER STOPS]
CAPTAIN, LOOK OUT!
AAH!
[THUD]
HE'S COMING
OUT OF IT NOW.
UH, THE THING...
THE THING...
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE ON BOARD
THE ENTERPRISE.
THE ROCK, I--
HOW'S YOUR HEAD?
ACHES.
YOU SAVED MY
LIFE DOWN THERE.
I WANT TO THANK YOU.
WHY SHOULDN'T I?
I HAVE SOME QUESTIONS
I WANT TO ASK YOU.
NOT NOW, JIM.
IT'S NECESSARY.
GO AHEAD.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS
A COMPUTER REPORT
OF THE EVIDENCE
YOU GAVE
AT YOUR FIRST
SCREENING.
IT CALLS YOU
A LIAR, LAZARUS.
FOR ONE THING,
THERE'S NO PLANET
AT THE LOCATION
YOU SAID
YOU CAME FROM.
THERE NEVER
HAS BEEN.
IF YOU WANT
HELP FROM US,
YOU BETTER START
TELLING THE TRUTH.
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME
IF I TOLD YOU.
TRY US.
ALL RIGHT.
I DISTORTED A FACT
IN THE INTEREST
OF SELF-PRESERVATION,
FOR MY HOLY CAUSE.
I NEEDED HELP,
NOT CENSURE,
FREEDOM, NOT CAPTIVITY
FOR BEING A MADMAN.
I WAS AFRAID THAT'S
WHAT YOU'D CALL ME
IF I TOLD YOU THE TRUTH.
I'LL HAVE THE TRUTH NOW.
MY PLANET...
MY EARTH...
OR WHAT'S LEFT OF IT,
IS DOWN THERE BENEATH US.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
MY SPACESHIP...
IS MORE THAT JUST THAT.
IT'S A TIME CHAMBER...
A TIME SHIP...
AND I...
I AM A TIME TRAVELER.
AND THIS THING
YOU SEARCH FOR
IS A
TIME TRAVELER, TOO?
OH, YES.
HE'S FLED ME ACROSS
ALL THE YEARS...
ALL THE EMPTY YEARS
TO A DEAD FUTURE...
ON A MURDERED PLANET
HE DESTROYED.
HELP ME!
GIVE ME THE TOOLS
I NEED TO KILL HIM!
THE CRYSTALS!
DON'T LET HIM
GET AWAY!
LAZARUS, YOU'VE
BEEN HURT, I KNOW.
I SYMPATHIZE
WITH YOU,
BUT I'VE GOT 430
OTHER MEN TO WORRY
ABOUT.
NOW, WHERE ARE
THOSE CRYSTALS?
I TOLD YOU.
HE'S GOT THEM.
HE TOOK THEM.
THE THING...
HE'S GOT
TO GET SOME
REST, JIM.
AND WOULD YOU GET
THAT MUSCLEMAN
OUT OF
MY SICK BAY?
DISMISSED.
HE'S IN
A LOT OF PAIN.
SOMETIMES PAIN CAN
DRIVE A MAN HARDER
THAN PLEASURE.
I'M SURE YOU
KNOW THAT, DOCTOR.
WELL, DON'T WORRY.
HE'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE,
NOT THIS TIME.
OH!
[LAZARUS GROANS]
WHAT HAVE WE GOT,
MR. SPOCK?
A MAGNETIC EFFECT
WHICH PRODUCES
A WINKING-OUT PHENOMENON,
A MYSTERIOUS,
UNIDENTIFIED SOURCE
OF RADIATION
ON THE PLANET,
LAZARUS, A WALKING
POWDER KEG,
YOUR RIP
IN THE UNIVERSE,
A SO-CALLED
MURDERING HUMANOID--
TRUE, CAPTAIN, BUT
MORE SIGNIFICANT TO ME
IS THE FACT THAT
OUR SHIP'S INSTRUMENTS
ARE SPECIFICALLY
DESIGNED TO LOCATE
AND IDENTIFY
ANY OBJECT
IN OUR UNIVERSE,
BE IT ENERGY
OR MATTER.
BUT BY USING
THOSE INSTRUMENTS,
YOU WERE UNABLE
TO IDENTIFY
THE SOURCE
OF THE RADIATION.
CORRECT...
WHICH WOULD SEEM
TO BE IMPOSSIBLE.
ARE THE INSTRUMENTS
IN ORDER?
PERFECT WORKING
CONDITION.
THEN WHAT YOU SAY
LEADS OBVIOUSLY...
TO ONE ALTERNATIVE.
THE SOURCE OF RADIATION IS
NOT FROM OUR UNIVERSE.
NOR IN OUR
UNIVERSE, CAPTAIN.
IT CAME FROM OUTSIDE.
OUTSIDE...
YES...
THAT WOULD
EXPLAIN A LOT.
ANOTHER UNIVERSE...
PERHAPS IN
ANOTHER DIMENSION...
OCCUPYING
THE SAME SPACE
AT THE SAME TIME.
POSSIBLE EXISTENCE
OF A PARALLEL UNIVERSE
HAS BEEN SCIENTIFICALLY
CONCEDED, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN IF...
ANOTHER UNIVERSE,
SAY A MINUS UNIVERSE,
CAME INTO CONTACT
WITH A POSITIVE UNIVERSE
SUCH AS OURS?
UNQUESTIONABLY
A WARP,
A DISTORTION
OF PHYSICAL LAWS
ON AN IMMENSE SCALE.
WHICH IS WHAT
WE'VE BEEN EXPERIENCING.
THE POINT WHERE
THEY COME INTO CONTACT,
COULDN'T THAT
BE DESCRIBED AS...
A HOLE?
INDEED.
I POINT OUT THAT A
HOLE IN THE UNIVERSE
OR IN A
SIMPLE CONTAINER
CAN EITHER ALLOW THE
CONTENTS TO ESCAPE...
OR WHAT IS
OUTSIDE TO ENTER.
THE INVASION THAT
COMMODORE BARSTOW SUSPECTED.
THERE HAS BEEN
NO EVIDENCE
OF A LARGE-SCALE
INVASION.
BUT A SMALL-SCALE
INVASION, MR. SPOCK?
WHAT IS YOUR ANALYSIS
OF THE MENTAL STATE
OF LAZARUS?
DIFFICULT, CAPTAIN.
ONE MOMENT, PARANOID,
THE NEXT,
CALM, MILD, RATIONAL.
ALMOST AS IF
HE WERE...TWO MEN.
YES, TWO MEN.
DIFFERENT,
BUT IDENTICAL.
AND A HOLE
IN THE UNIVERSE.
NO, NOT A HOLE.
A DOOR.
THROUGH WHICH
THESE TWO BEINGS
ARE SOMEHOW
ENABLED TO PASS.
TAKE A LOOK AT LAZARUS.
ONE MINUTE HE'S
AT THE POINT OF DEATH,
THE NEXT,
HE'S ALIVE, WELL,
STRONG AS A BULL.
THE CUT ON HIS FOREHEAD.
FIRST HE HAS IT,
THEN IT'S GONE,
THEN HE HAS IT AGAIN.
WHICH IS
PHYSICALLY IMPOSSIBLE
FOR ONE MAN.
QUITE RIGHT.
UNQUESTIONABLY,
THERE ARE TWO OF HIM.
BUT WHAT'S GOING ON?
THIS LEAPING FROM
UNIVERSE TO UNIVERSE...
THIS WILD TALK ABOUT
A MURDERING CREATURE
WHO DESTROYS
CIVILIZATIONS--
WHAT'S THE PURPOSE?
JIM, MADNESS
HAS NO PURPOSE...
OR REASON...
BUT IT MAY
HAVE A GOAL.
HE MUST BE
STOPPED, HELD...
DESTROYED
IF NECESSARY.
I DON'T FOLLOW YOU.
TWO PARALLEL UNIVERSES--
PROJECT THIS--
ONE POSITIVE,
THE OTHER NEGATIVE...
OR, MORE SPECIFICALLY,
ONE, MATTER...
THE OTHER, ANTIMATTER.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING?
MATTER AND ANTIMATTER
HAVE A TENDENCY
TO CANCEL
EACH OTHER OUT...
VIOLENTLY.
PRECISELY.
UNDER CERTAIN
CONDITIONS,
WHEN TWO
IDENTICAL PARTICLES
OF MATTER AND
ANTIMATTER MEET...
LIKE LAZARUS...
IDENTICAL...
LIKE BOTH LAZARUS...
ONLY ONE IS MATTER
AND THE OTHER ANTIMATTER.
IF THEY MEET...
ANNIHILATION, JIM.
TOTAL, COMPLETE,
ABSOLUTE ANNIHILATION.
OF EVERYTHING
THAT EXISTS...
EVERYWHERE.
[BEEP]
THE ENERGIZER--
IT'S SHORTED.
GET OUT OF HERE.
SOUND THE ALARM.
COME ON, YOU,
TOO, LIEUTENANT.
I'VE GOT TO STAY--
THE WHOLE THING
MIGHT BLOW!
[COUGHING]
[SIREN WAILS]
ENGINEERING
CALLING BRIDGE.
FIRE!
FIRE, THE
ENERGIZING CIRCUITS!
[SIREN WAILS]
FIRE, CAPTAIN.
ENGINEERING.
SITUATION CRITICAL.
ALL AVAILABLE PERSONNEL,
ON THE DOUBLE.
SPOCK, WITH ME.
REPORT.
UNDER CONTROL, SIR,
BUT IT COULDN'T HAVE
STARTED BY ITSELF.
LAZARUS--
A TRICK TO GET
THE CRYSTALS.
SIR, YOU SHOULDN'T
BE IN HERE.
OH, I DIDN'T KNOW.
HE'S PROBABLY BEAMING DOWN
WITH THE CRYSTALS RIGHT NOW.
I'M GOING AFTER HIM.
YOU ORGANIZE A SECURITY DETAIL.
FOLLOW ME AS
SOON AS YOU CAN.
SPOCK TO BRIDGE.
I'LL GET YOU NOW.
I HAVE A THRESHOLD.
RUN, RUN...
I'LL GET YOU NOW.
[SIREN WAILS]
ENERGIZE.
IT'S DONE, IT'S DONE.
FINISHED, FINISHED.
IT'S DONE.
IT'S DONE,
LAZARUS...
NO! DON'T!
NOT YOU!
NO!
WELCOME, CAPTAIN.
I WASN'T EXPECTING YOU.
NO...
HIM.
YES, HIM.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
NOT COMPLETELY.
THIS IS A
PARALLEL UNIVERSE?
OF COURSE.
ANTIMATTER?
HERE, YES.
AND IF IDENTICAL
PARTICLES MEET...
THE END OF EVERYTHING.
CIVILIZATION,
EXISTENCE--
ALL GONE.
I TRIED TO
STOP HIM, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S WHY I TOOK
YOUR DILITHIUM CRYSTALS.
HE HAS TWO MORE.
THAT'S VERY
BAD, CAPTAIN.
IF HE COMES THROUGH
AT A TIME OF
HIS OWN CHOOSING...
WELL, I THINK
IF WE HURRY
AND YOU WILL HELP ME,
HE CAN YET
STILL BE STOPPED.
THERE'S LITTLE TIME LEFT.
HE MEANT
TO COME THROUGH.
WHEN YOU ACCIDENTALLY
PASSED THROUGH,
IT DRAINED HIS CRYSTALS.
IT'LL TAKE HIM
ABOUT 10 MINUTES
TO RE-ENERGIZE
WITH THE EQUIPMENT
ABOARD HIS SHIP.
THAT SHOULD GIVE US
ENOUGH TIME.
EXACTLY WHAT
DID I PASS THROUGH?
THAT'S HARD TO
EXPLAIN, CAPTAIN.
I CALL IT
AN ALTERNATIVE WARP.
IT'S SORT OF A NEGATIVE
MAGNETIC CORRIDOR
WHERE THE TWO
PARALLEL UNIVERSES MEET.
IT'S SORT OF
A SAFETY VALVE.
IT KEEPS ETERNITY
FROM BLOWING UP.
THIS CORRIDOR...
IS IT WHAT CAUSED
THE MAGNETIC EFFECT,
THE WINKING-OUT
PHENOMENON?
PRECISELY, CAPTAIN...
BUT NOT BECAUSE
OF ITS EXISTENCE...
BECAUSE...
BECAUSE MY FOE ENTERED.
THE CORRIDOR
IS LIKE A PRISON
WITH EXPLOSIVES
AT THE DOOR.
OPEN THE DOOR,
AND THE EXPLOSIVES
MIGHT GO OFF.
STAY INSIDE...
AND THE UNIVERSE
IS SAFE.
BOTH UNIVERSES,
CAPTAIN...
YOURS AND MINE.
SURELY, LAZARUS MUST
REALIZE WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF YOU SHOULD MEET
FACE-TO-FACE
OUTSIDE THE CORRIDOR.
OF COURSE HE
KNOWS, CAPTAIN,
BUT HE'S MAD.
YOU HEARD HIM.
HE'S LOST HIS MIND.
WHEN OUR PEOPLE
FOUND A WAY
TO SLIP
THROUGH THE WARP
AND PROVE
ANOTHER UNIVERSE,
AN IDENTICAL ONE,
EXISTED,
IT WAS TOO
MUCH FOR HIM.
HE COULD NOT LIVE
KNOWING THAT I LIVED.
HE BECAME OBSESSED
WITH THE IDEA
OF DESTROYING ME.
AND THE FACT THAT
IT MEANT HIS OWN
DESTRUCTION
AND EVERYTHING ELSE
MEANT NOTHING TO HIM.
SO YOU'RE
THE TERRIBLE THING,
THE MURDERING MONSTER...
THE CREATURE?
YES, CAPTAIN.
OR HE IS.
IT DEPENDS ON
YOUR POINT OF VIEW,
DOESN'T IT?
IT'S READY, CAPTAIN.
IF WE CAN FORCE HIM
INTO THE CORRIDOR
WHILE I'M WAITING,
WE CAN PUT
AN END TO THIS.
BUT IF HE
COMES THROUGH
AT A TIME OF
HIS OWN CHOOSING
AND BREAKS
INTO THIS UNIVERSE
TO FIND ME--
I UNDERSTAND.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT ME TO DO?
FIND HIM.
FORCE HIM THROUGH
HIS THRESHOLD,
WHILE I'M
WAITING FOR HIM,
INTO THE CORRIDOR...
AND I'LL
HOLD HIM THERE.
YOU CAN'T
HOLD HIM FOREVER.
CAN'T I, CAPTAIN?
YOU DESTROY HIS SHIP.
BUT IF I DESTROY
HIS SHIP,
WON'T YOURS
ALSO BE DESTROYED?
IT WILL.
AND YOUR DOOR
WILL BE CLOSED.
YES, AND SO WILL HIS.
YOU'LL BE TRAPPED INSIDE
THAT CORRIDOR WITH HIM
FOREVER...
AT EACH OTHER'S THROATS
THROUGHOUT TIME.
IS IT SUCH A
LARGE PRICE TO PAY
FOR THE SAFETY
OF TWO UNIVERSES?
I'M READY.
SEND HIM TO ME.
I'LL BE WAITING.
LAZARUS.
STAND BACK.
NO!
NO, I'M NOT READY!
I'M NOT READY!
STOP!
TAKE THESE CRYSTALS
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
WE MUST DESTROY
THAT SHIP COMPLETELY.
WHAT OF LAZARUS?
AND WHAT OF LAZARUS?
[SIREN WAILS]
ACTIVATE PHASER BANKS.
PHASER BANKS
ACTIVATED.
STAND BY TO FIRE.
PHASERS
STANDING BY, SIR.
FIRE PHASERS.
ALL RIGHT, MR. LESLEY,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR ONE.
WARP ONE,
SIR.
EVERYTHING'S ALL
RIGHT, MR. SPOCK...
FOR US.
THERE IS, OF COURSE,
NO ESCAPE
FOR THEM, SIR.
THERE IS, OF COURSE,
NO ESCAPE.
HOW WOULD IT BE...
TRAPPED FOREVER
WITH A RAGING MADMAN
AT YOUR THROAT
UNTIL TIME ITSELF
CAME TO A STOP?
FOR ETERNITY?
HOW WOULD IT BE?
CAPTAIN...
THE UNIVERSE IS SAFE.
FOR YOU AND ME.
BUT WHAT OF LAZARUS?