[BEEPING]
STAY ON TOP OF IT,
MR. SULU.
WE'RE HOLDING
ORBIT, SIR.
THE HELM
IS SLUGGISH.
CONTROL CIRCUITS
THREATENING
TO OVERLOAD, CAPTAIN.
UNDERSTOOD, ENGINEER.
MR. SPOCK.
WE CAN'T AVOID
THESE AREAS
OF TURBULENCE.
I BELIEVE WE'LL
HAVE THEM PLOTTED
IN A FEW MORE ORBITS,
CAPTAIN.
SICK BAY, TO BRIDGE.
SWITCHING TO MANUAL,
CAPTAIN.
WE MAINTAIN
THIS ORBIT?
MR. SPOCK?
THIS IS OF GREAT
SCIENTIFIC IMPORTANCE,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE ACTUALLY PASSING
THROUGH RIPPLES IN TIME.
MAINTAIN ORBIT.
OPEN THE CHANNEL
TO STAR FLEET COMMAND.
YES, SIR.
PRECAUTIONARY MEASURE,
LIEUTENANT.
BROADCAST
TO STAR FLEET COMMAND
MY PAST WEEK'S LOG ENTRY,
STARTING WITH THE UNUSUAL
READINGS ON THE INSTRUMENTS
AND HOW THEY LED US HERE.
INFORM STAR FLEET COMMAND
THAT APPARENTLY...
SOMETHING OR SOMEONE
DOWN ON THIS PLANET...
BONES.
CAN AFFECT CHANGES IN TIME,
CAUSING TURBULENT WAVES
OF SPACE DISPLACEMENT.
SOME HEART FLUTTER.
BETTER RISK A FEW DROPS
OF CORDRUZINE.
TRICKY STUFF.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU WANT TO RISK--
[HISS]
YOU WERE ABOUT
TO MAKE A MEDICAL
COMMENT, JIM?
WHO, ME, DOCTOR?
WE'RE GUIDING AROUND
MOST OF THE TIME RIPPLES
NOW, CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK?
ALL PLOTTED BUT ONE,
CAPTAIN.
COMING UP ON IT NOW.
SEEMS TO BE FAIRLY HEAVY
DISPLACEMENT.
[HISS]
BONES!
BACK TO YOUR POSITIONS.
THE HYPO, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS SET
FOR CORDRUZINE.
EMPTY.
COMMUNICATIONS,
EMERGENCY
MEDICAL TEAM.
AAH!
KILLERS! ASSASSINS!
I WON'T LET YOU!
I'LL KILL YOU FIRST!
YOU WON'T GET ME!
MURDERERS!
KILLERS!
SECURITY ALERT.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL ENTRY.
TWO DROPS OF CORDRUZINE
CAN SAVE A MAN'S LIFE.
A HUNDRED TIMES
THAT AMOUNT
HAS JUST ACCIDENTALLY
BEEN PUMPED
INTO DR. McCOY'S BODY.
IN A STRANGE, WILD FRENZY,
HE HAS FLED
THE SHIP'S BRIDGE.
ALL CONNECTING DECKS
HAVE BEEN PLACED ON ALERT.
WE HAVE NO WAY
OF KNOWING
IF THE MADNESS
IS PERMANENT OR TEMPORARY
OR IN WHAT DIRECTION
IT WILL DRIVE McCOY.
CONTINUE ALERT,
DECKS 4 THROUGH 11.
THE MEDICAL
DEPARTMENT KNOWS
AS LITTLE AS WE DO.
IN DOSAGES
APPROACHING THIS,
THERE'S SOME RECORD
OF WILD PARANOIA.
CONFIRMED BY THE LIBRARY
RECORD TAPES, CAPTAIN.
SUBJECTS FAILED
TO RECOGNIZE
ACQUAINTANCES,
BECAME
HYSTERICALLY CONVINCED
THAT THEY WERE
IN MORTAL DANGER,
AND WERE SEEKING ESCAPE
AT ANY COST.
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS
TO HIMSELF
OR TO ANYONE ELSE
WHO MIGHT--
BRIDGE, SECURITY.
ALERT, ALERT!
BRIDGE HERE. GO AHEAD.
SECURITY 054,
SIR.
WE JUST FOUND
THE TRANSPORTER
CHIEF INJURED.
CAPTAIN, DR. McCOY
HAS BEAMED HIMSELF
DOWN TO THE PLANET.
AND THE TRANSPORTER
AT THAT TIME, CAPTAIN,
WAS FOCUSED
ON THE CENTER
OF THE TIME DISTURBANCE.
SO WHATEVER'S
DOWN THERE,
McCOY'S
IN THE HEART OF IT.
SET UP
A LANDING PARTY.
LET'S GO GET HIM.
KIRK OUT.
THESE RUINS EXTEND
TO THE HORIZON.
BEGIN RECORDING.
RECORDING, SIR.
AND OF
CONSIDERABLE AGE--
ON THE ORDER
OF 10,000
CENTURIES OLD.
DETAIL, FAN OUT.
WHAT IS THIS THING,
MR. SPOCK?
IT SEEMS TO BE PULSATING
WITH POWER OF SOME KIND.
ANALYSIS, PLEASE.
UNBELIEVABLE, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S FUNNY.
THIS SINGLE OBJECT
IS THE SOURCE
OF ALL THE TIME
DISPLACEMENT.
EXPLAIN.
I CAN'T.
FOR THIS TO DO
WHAT IT DOES
IS IMPOSSIBLE
BY ANY SCIENCE
I UNDERSTAND.
IT IS OPERATING
EVEN NOW...
PUTTING OUT
WAVES AND WAVES OF
TIME DISPLACEMENT,
WHICH WE
PICKED UP MILLIONS
OF MILES AWAY.
LANDING PARTY
TO ENTERPRISE.
NO SIGN OF DR. McCOY.
SEARCH PROGRESSING.
INCREDIBLE POWER.
IT CAN'T BE
A MACHINE
AS WE UNDERSTAND
MECHANICS.
THEN WHAT IS IT?
A QUESTION.
SINCE BEFORE YOUR SUN
BURNED HOT IN SPACE
AND BEFORE
YOUR RACE WAS BORN,
I HAVE AWAITED
A QUESTION.
WHAT ARE YOU?
I AM THE GUARDIAN
OF FOREVER.
ARE YOU MACHINE
OR BEING?
I AM BOTH AND NEITHER.
I AM MY OWN BEGINNING,
MY OWN ENDING.
I SEE NO REASON
FOR ANSWERS
TO BE COUCHED
IN RIDDLES.
I ANSWER AS SIMPLY AS
YOUR LEVEL OF UNDERSTANDING
MAKES POSSIBLE.
A TIME PORTAL, CAPTAIN--
A GATEWAY TO OTHER TIMES
AND DIMENSIONS,
IF I'M CORRECT.
AS CORRECT AS POSSIBLE
FOR YOU.
YOUR SCIENCE KNOWLEDGE
IS OBVIOUSLY PRIMITIVE.
REALLY?
ANNOYED, SPOCK?
BEHOLD.
A GATEWAY TO YOUR OWN PAST,
IF YOU WISH.
McCoy: KILLERS!
KILLERS!
I WON'T LET YOU GET ME!
I'LL KILL YOU FIRST!
ASSASSINS! MURDERERS!
KILLERS!
SPOCK!
IF THAT IS A DOORWAY
BACK THROUGH TIME,
COULD WE
SOMEHOW TAKE BONES
BACK A DAY IN TIME,
THEN...
RELIVE THE ACCIDENT,
THIS TIME BE CERTAIN
THAT THE HYPO ACCIDENT
IS AVOIDED?
LOOK AT THE SPEED
WITH WHICH THE CENTURIES
ARE PASSING, CAPTAIN.
TO STEP THROUGH
ON PRECISELY
THE DAY WE WISH...
GUARDIAN.
CAN YOU CHANGE
THE SPEED AT WHICH
YESTERDAY PASSES?
I WAS MADE TO OFFER
THE PAST IN THIS MANNER.
I CANNOT CHANGE.
STRANGELY COMPELLING,
ISN'T IT?
TO STEP THROUGH THERE...
AND LOSE ONESELF
IN ANOTHER WORLD.
I AM A FOOL.
OUR TRICORDER
IS CAPABLE OF RECORDING
EVEN AT THIS SPEED.
I'VE MISSED
TAPING CENTURIES
OF LIVING HISTORY
WHICH NO MAN BEFORE
HAS EVER--
DR. McCOY!
BONES, NO!
WHERE IS HE?
HE HAS PASSED INTO...
WHAT WAS.
CAPTAIN, I'VE
LOST CONTACT
WITH THE SHIP.
I WAS TALKING
TO THEM.
SUDDENLY,
IT WENT DEAD.
NO STATIC,
JUST NOTHING.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTTY.
NOTHING WRONG WITH
THE COMMUNICATOR, SIR.
YOUR VESSEL,
YOUR BEGINNING,
ALL THAT YOU KNEW
IS GONE.
McCOY...
HAS SOMEHOW
CHANGED HISTORY.
YOU MEAN WE'RE
STRANDED DOWN HERE?
WITH NO PAST,
NO FUTURE?
CAPTAIN,
I'M FRIGHTENED.
EARTH'S NOT THERE,
AT LEAST
NOT THE EARTH WE KNOW.
WE'RE TOTALLY ALONE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
NO STAR DATE.
FOR US,
TIME DOES NOT EXIST.
McCOY, BACK SOMEWHERE
IN THE PAST,
HAS EFFECTED A CHANGE
IN THE COURSE OF TIME.
ALL EARTH HISTORY
HAS BEEN CHANGED.
THERE IS NO STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
WE HAVE ONLY ONE CHANCE.
WE HAVE ASKED
THE GUARDIAN
TO SHOW US
EARTH'S HISTORY AGAIN.
SPOCK AND I WILL GO BACK
INTO TIME OURSELVES
AND ATTEMPT TO SET RIGHT
WHATEVER IT WAS
THAT McCOY CHANGED.
I WAS RECORDING IMAGES
AT THE TIME McCOY LEFT--
A RATHER BARBARIC PERIOD
IN YOUR AMERICAN HISTORY.
I BELIEVE
I CAN APPROXIMATE
JUST WHEN TO JUMP,
PERHAPS WITHIN A MONTH
OF THE CORRECT TIME.
A WEEK,
IF WE'RE FORTUNATE.
MAKE SURE
WE ARRIVE BEFORE
McCOY GOT THERE.
IT'S VITAL
WE STOP HIM
BEFORE HE DOES
WHATEVER IT WAS
THAT CHANGED
ALL HISTORY.
GUARDIAN.
IF WE ARE SUCCESSFUL...
THEN YOU WILL BE RETURNED.
IT WILL BE AS THOUGH
NONE OF YOU HAD GONE.
CAPTAIN,
IT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE.
EVEN IF YOU'RE ABLE
TO FIND THE RIGHT DATE...
THEN EVEN
FINDING McCOY
WOULD BE A MIRACLE.
THERE IS NO ALTERNATIVE.
SCOTTY...
WHEN YOU THINK
YOU'VE WAITED LONG ENOUGH,
EACH OF YOU
WILL HAVE TO TRY IT,
EVEN IF YOU FAIL.
AT LEAST YOU'LL BE ALIVE
IN SOME PAST WORLD SOMEWHERE.
AYE.
SECONDS NOW, SIR.
STAND BY.
GOOD LUCK, GENTLEMEN.
HAPPINESS
AT LEAST, SIR.
AND...
NOW.
I'VE SEEN OLD PHOTOGRAPHS
OF THIS PERIOD.
AN ECONOMIC UPHEAVAL
HAD OCCURRED.
IT WAS CALLED
DEPRESSION,
CIRCA 1930.
QUITE BARBARIC.
WE SEEM TO BE COSTUMED
A LITTLE OUT OF STEP
WITH THE TIME.
I'M AFRAID
I'M GOING TO BE
DIFFICULT TO EXPLAIN
IN ANY CASE,
CAPTAIN.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
IF WE CAN'T DISGUISE YOU,
WE'LL FIND SOME WAY OF...
EXPLAINING YOU.
THAT SHOULD PROVE
INTERESTING.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
[HORN HONKS]
LOOK OUT, WILL YOU?
WHY DON'T YOU WATCH
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
THEFT, CAPTAIN?
WELL, WE'LL STEAL
FROM THE RICH
AND GIVE BACK
TO THE POOR LATER.
I THINK I'M GOING
TO LIKE THIS CENTURY--
SIMPLE, EASIER TO MANAGE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
ANY DIFFICULTY EXPLAINING--
AHEM.
WELL?
YOU'RE A POLICE OFFICER.
I RECOGNIZE THE TRADITIONAL
ACCOUTREMENTS.
YOU WERE SAYING
YOU'LL HAVE
NO TROUBLE
EXPLAINING IT.
MY FRIEND
IS OBVIOUSLY CHINESE.
I SEE YOU'VE NOTICED
THE EARS.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY EASY
TO EXPLAIN.
PERHAPS
THE UNFORTUNATE
ACCIDENT
I HAD AS A CHILD.
THE UNFORTUNATE ACCIDENT
HE HAD AS A CHILD.
HE CAUGHT HIS HEAD
IN A MECHANICAL...
RICE PICKER,
BUT FORTUNATELY,
THERE WAS
AN AMERICAN MISSIONARY
LIVING CLOSE BY
WHO WAS ACTUALLY
A, UH...
SKILLED PLASTIC SURGEON
IN CIVILIAN LIFE.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT!
DROP THOSE BUNDLES
AND PUT YOUR HANDS ON
THAT WALL THERE! COME ON!
HOW CARELESS
OF YOUR WIFE
TO LET YOU
GO OUT THAT WAY.
OH, YES,
IT'S QUITE UNTIDY.
HERE,
LET ME HELP YOU.
OH!
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
[DOG BARKING]
YOU WERE ACTUALLY ENJOYING
MY PREDICAMENT BACK THERE.
AT TIMES,
YOU SEEM QUITE HUMAN.
CAPTAIN,
I HARDLY BELIEVE
THAT INSULTS
ARE WITHIN
YOUR PREROGATIVE
AS MY COMMANDING
OFFICER.
SORRY.
TIME WE FACED
THE UNPLEASANT FACTS.
FIRST, I BELIEVE
WE HAVE ABOUT A WEEK
BEFORE McCOY ARRIVES,
BUT WE CAN'T BE CERTAIN.
ARRIVES WHERE--
HONOLULU, BOISE,
SAN DIEGO?
WHY NOT OUTER MONGOLIA,
FOR THAT MATTER?
THERE IS A THEORY.
THERE COULD BE
SOME LOGIC
TO THE BELIEF
THAT TIME IS FLUID,
LIKE A RIVER--
WITH CURRENTS,
EDDIES, BACKWASH.
AND THE SAME CURRENTS
THAT SWEPT McCOY
TO A CERTAIN TIME
AND PLACE
MIGHT SWEEP US
THERE, TOO.
UNLESS THAT
IS TRUE, CAPTAIN,
WE HAVE NO HOPE.
FRUSTRATING--
LOCKED IN HERE
IS THE PLACE AND MOMENT
OF HIS ARRIVAL,
EVEN THE IMAGES
OF WHAT HE DID.
IF ONLY I COULD TIE
THIS TRICORDER IN
WITH THE SHIP'S COMPUTERS
FOR A FEW MOMENTS.
COULDN'T YOU
BUILD SOME FORM OF
COMPUTER AID HERE?
IN THIS ZINC-PLATED
VACUUM-TUBED CULTURE?
YES, WELL,
IT WOULD POSE
AN EXTREMELY
COMPLEX PROBLEM
IN LOGIC, MR. SPOCK.
EXCUSE ME.
I SOMETIMES EXPECT
TOO MUCH OF YOU.
WHO'S THERE?
EXCUSE US, MISS.
WE DIDN'T MEAN
TO TRESPASS.
IT'S COLD OUTSIDE.
A LIE IS A VERY POOR WAY
TO SAY HELLO.
IT ISN'T THAT COLD.
NO.
WE WERE BEING CHASED
BY A POLICEMAN.
WHY?
FOR THESE CLOTHES.
WE STOLE THEM.
WE DIDN'T HAVE
ANY MONEY.
WELL, I COULD DO WITH
SOME HELP AROUND HERE--
DOING DISHES, SWEEPING,
GENERAL CLEANING.
AT WHAT RATE
OF PAYMENT?
I NEED RADIO TUBES
AND SO FORTH.
MY HOBBY.
15 CENTS AN HOUR
FOR 10 HOURS A DAY.
WHAT ARE YOUR NAMES?
MINE IS JIM KIRK.
HIS IS...
SPOCK.
I'M EDITH KEELER.
WELL, YOU CAN START
BY CLEANING UP DOWN HERE.
EXCUSE ME, MISS.
WHERE ARE WE?
YOU'RE IN
THE 21st STREET MISSION.
DO YOU RUN THIS PLACE?
INDEED I DO, MR. KIRK.
RADIO TUBES
AND SO ON.
I APPROVE OF HOBBIES,
MR. SPOCK.
GOOD EVENING.
YOU'LL BE SORRY.
WHY?
YOU EXPECT TO EAT
FOR FREE OR SOMETHING?
YOU GOT TO LISTEN
TO GOODY TWO-SHOES.
NOW, AS I'M SURE SOMEBODY
OUT THERE HAS SAID,
IT'S TIME TO PAY
FOR THE SOUP.
NOT THAT SHE'S
A BAD-LOOKING BROAD,
BUT IF SHE
REALLY WANTED
TO HELP OUT
A FELLA IN NEED--
SHUT UP.
I WANT TO HEAR
WHAT SHE HAS TO SAY.
YES, OF COURSE,
CAPTAIN.
NOW, LET'S START BY GETTING
ONE THING STRAIGHT.
I'M NOT A DO-GOODER.
IF YOU'RE A BUM,
IF YOU CAN'T
BREAK OFF OF THE BOOZE
OR WHATEVER IT IS
THAT MAKES YOU A BAD RISK,
THEN GET OUT.
NOW I DON'T PRETEND
TO TELL YOU
HOW TO FIND HAPPINESS
AND LOVE
WHEN EVERY DAY
IS A JUST STRUGGLE
TO SURVIVE,
BUT I DO INSIST
THAT YOU DO SURVIVE
BECAUSE THE DAYS
AND THE YEARS AHEAD
ARE WORTH LIVING FOR.
ONE DAY SOON...
MAN IS GOING TO BE ABLE TO
HARNESS INCREDIBLE ENERGIES,
MAYBE EVEN THE ATOM.
ENERGIES THAT
COULD ULTIMATELY HURL US
TO OTHER WORLDS
IN...IN SOME SORT
OF SPACESHIP,
AND THE MEN
THAT REACH OUT INTO SPACE
WILL BE ABLE
TO FIND WAYS
TO FEED THE HUNGRY MILLIONS
OF THE WORLD
AND TO CURE
THEIR DISEASES.
THEY WILL BE ABLE
TO FIND A WAY
TO GIVE EACH MAN HOPE
AND A COMMON FUTURE,
AND THOSE ARE THE DAYS
WORTH LIVING FOR.
OUR DESERTS WILL BLOOM.
DEVELOPMENT
OF ATOMIC POWER
IS YEARS AWAY.
SPACE FLIGHT,
YEARS AFTER THAT.
SPECULATION.
GIFTED INSIGHT.
BUT IT WILL COME.
I FIND HER
MOST UNCOMMON,
MR. SPOCK.
MR. KIRK.
YOU ARE
UNCOMMON WORKMEN.
THAT BASEMENT
LOOKS LIKE IT'S BEEN
SCRUBBED AND POLISHED.
THEN WE CAN REPORT BACK
FOR OTHER WORK?
YES. 7:00
IN THE MORNING.
DO YOU HAVE A FLOP
FOR THE NIGHT?
A WHAT?
YOU REALLY ARE NEW
AT THIS, AREN'T YOU?
A FLOP IS
A PLACE TO SLEEP.
OH.
THERE'S A VACANT ROOM
AT THE PLACE
WHERE I LIVE
FOR $2.00 A WEEK.
IF YOU WANT TO,
I'LL TAKE YOU THERE.
THANK YOU.
WE HAVE A FLOP.
WE HAVE A WHAT,
CAPTAIN?
A PLACE TO SLEEP.
ONE MIGHT HAVE SAID SO
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
[BEEPING AND SQUEALING]
[BEEPING AND SQUEALING STOPS]
CAPTAIN, I MUST HAVE
SOME PLATINUM.
A SMALL BLOCK
WOULD BE SUFFICIENT--
5 OR 6 POUNDS.
BY PASSING CERTAIN
CIRCUITS THROUGH THERE
TO BE USED AS
A DUO-DYNETIC FIELD CORE--
MR. SPOCK, I'VE
BROUGHT YOU SOME
ASSORTED VEGETABLES,
BALONEY
AND A HARD ROLL
FOR MYSELF,
AND I'VE SPENT
THE OTHER 9/10
OF OUR COMBINED
SALARIES FOR
THE LAST THREE DAYS
ON FILLING
THIS ORDER FOR YOU.
MR. SPOCK,
THIS BAG DOESN'T
CONTAIN PLATINUM,
SILVER, OR GOLD,
NOR IS IT LIKELY TO
IN THE NEAR FUTURE.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO USE EQUIPMENT
WHICH IS HARDLY VERY FAR
AHEAD OF STONE KNIVES
AND BEARSKINS.
McCOY WILL BE ALONG
IN A FEW DAYS,
PERHAPS SOONER.
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE
THAT THESE CURRENTS
IN TIME
WILL BRING US
TOGETHER.
THIS HAS TO WORK.
CAPTAIN...
CAPTAIN,
IN THREE WEEKS,
AT THIS RATE,
POSSIBLY A MONTH,
I MIGHT REACH
THE FIRST MNEMONIC
MEMORY CIRCUITS.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
YOUR CAP.
IF YOU CAN LEAVE
RIGHT AWAY,
I CAN GET YOU
5 HOURS' WORK
AT 22 CENTS AN HOUR.
WHAT--WHAT ON EARTH
IS THAT?
I AM ENDEAVORING,
MA'AM,
TO CONSTRUCT
A MNEMONIC
MEMORY CIRCUIT
USING STONE KNIVES
AND BEARSKINS.
CAPTAIN.
TOOLS...
FOR FINELY
DETAILED WORK.
THAT TOOLBOX WAS LOCKED
WITH A COMBINATION LOCK,
AND YOU OPENED IT
LIKE A REAL PRO.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
I NEEDED THE FINE TOOLS
FOR MY RADIO WORK.
THEY'D HAVE BEEN
RETURNED IN THE MORNING.
I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T--
IF MR. SPOCK SAYS
THAT HE NEEDS
THE TOOLS
AND THAT THEY'D
BE RETURNED
TOMORROW MORNING,
YOU CAN BET YOUR
REPUTATION ON THAT,
MISS KEELER.
ON ONE CONDITION...
WALK ME HOME?
I STILL HAVE
A FEW QUESTIONS
I'D LIKE TO ASK
ABOUT YOU TWO.
OH, AND DON'T GIVE ME
THAT "QUESTIONS ABOUT
LITTLE OLD US?" LOOK.
YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO
HOW OUT OF PLACE
YOU TWO ARE AROUND HERE.
INTERESTING.
WHERE WOULD YOU ESTIMATE
WE BELONG, MISS KEELER?
YOU?
AT HIS SIDE,
AS IF YOU'VE
ALWAYS BEEN THERE
AND ALWAYS WILL.
AND YOU...
YOU BELONG...
IN ANOTHER PLACE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE OR HOW.
I'LL FIGURE IT OUT
EVENTUALLY.
I'LL FINISH
WITH THE FURNACE.
"CAPTAIN"?
EVEN WHEN HE DOESN'T
SAY IT, HE DOES.
Man on radio:
♪ GOOD NIGHT, SWEETHEART ♪
♪ THOUGH I'M NOT BESIDE YOU ♪
♪ STILL, MY LOVE
WILL GUIDE YOU... ♪
WHY DOES SPOCK
CALL YOU CAPTAIN?
WERE YOU
IN THE WAR TOGETHER?
WE SERVED TOGETHER.
AND YOU DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT?
WHY?
I--
DID YOU--DID YOU DO
SOMETHING WRONG?
ARE YOU AFRAID
OF SOMETHING?
WHATEVER IT IS,
LET ME HELP.
"LET ME HELP."
A HUNDRED YEARS
OR SO FROM NOW,
I BELIEVE,
A FAMOUS NOVELIST
WILL WRITE A CLASSIC
USING THAT THEME.
HE'LL RECOMMEND
THOSE THREE WORDS
EVEN OVER
"I LOVE YOU."
CENTURIES FROM NOW?
WHO IS HE?
WHERE DOES HE COME--
WHERE WILL HE
COME FROM?
SILLY QUESTION.
WANT TO HEAR
A SILLY ANSWER?
YES.
A PLANET...
CIRCLING THAT
FAR LEFT STAR
IN ORION'S BELT.
SEE?
HOW ARE THE STONE KNIVES
AND BEARSKINS?
I MAY HAVE FOUND
OUR FOCAL POINT IN TIME.
I THINK YOU MAY
ALSO FIND YOU HAVE
A CONNECTION
BURNING SOMEPLACE.
YES. I'M OVERLOADING
THOSE LINES.
I BELIEVE WE'LL HAVE
OUR ANSWER ON THIS
SCREEN, CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
AND, CAPTAIN...
YOU MAY FIND THIS
A BIT DISTRESSING.
WELL, LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU HAVE.
I'VE SLOWED DOWN
THE RECORDING WE MADE
FROM THE TIME VORTEX.
"FEBRUARY 23, 1936."
SIX YEARS FROM NOW.
"THE PRESIDENT
AND...
"EDITH KEELER...
CONFERRED FOR
SOME TIME TODAY--"
[BZZZT]
HOW BAD?
BAD ENOUGH.
THE PRESIDENT
AND EDITH KEELER.
IT WOULD SEEM
UNLIKELY, JIM.
A FEW MOMENTS AGO,
I READ A 1930
NEWSPAPER ARTICLE.
WE KNOW HER FUTURE.
WITHIN SIX YEARS
FROM NOW,
SHE'LL BECOME
VERY IMPORTANT,
NATIONALLY FAMOUS.
OR, CAPTAIN,
EDITH KEELER
WILL DIE THIS YEAR.
I SAW HER OBITUARY.
SOME SORT OF
TRAFFIC ACCIDENT.
YOU MUST BE MISTAKEN.
THEY BOTH CAN'T BE TRUE.
CAPTAIN, EDITH KEELER IS
THE FOCAL POINT IN TIME
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR,
THE POINT IN TIME THAT
BOTH WE AND DR. McCOY
HAVE BEEN DRAWN TO.
SHE HAS TWO
POSSIBLE FUTURES THEN,
AND, DEPENDING ON WHETHER
SHE LIVES OR DIES,
ALL OF HISTORY
WILL BE CHANGED.
AND McCOY...
IS THE RANDOM ELEMENT.
IN HIS CONDITION,
WHAT DOES HE DO?
DOES HE KILL HER?
OR PERHAPS
HE PREVENTS HER
FROM BEING KILLED.
WE DON'T KNOW WHICH.
GET THIS THING FIXED.
WE MUST FIND OUT
BEFORE McCOY ARRIVES.
CAPTAIN...
SUPPOSE WE DISCOVER
THAT, IN ORDER
TO SET THINGS
STRAIGHT AGAIN,
EDITH KEELER
MUST DIE?
ASSASSINS!
MURDERERS!
YOU!
WHAT PLANET IS THIS?
NO!
DON'T RUN!
I WON'T KILL YOU!
IT'S THEY
WHO DO THE KILLING!
DON'T RUN!
I WON'T KILL YOU!
WHY?
WHAT IS SO FUNNY
ABOUT MAN REACHING
FOR THE MOON?
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I JUST KNOW,
THAT'S ALL.
I--I FEEL IT,
AND MORE,
I THINK THAT ONE DAY
THEY'RE GOING TO
TAKE ALL THE MONEY
THAT THEY SPEND NOW
ON WAR AND DEATH--
AND MAKE THEM SPEND IT
ON LIFE.
YES.
YOU SEE THE SAME
THINGS THAT I DO.
WE SPEAK
THE SAME LANGUAGE.
THE VERY SAME.
OHH!
I'M GLAD YOU
GOT AWAY, TOO.
YEAH. I--
WHY DO YOU THINK
THEY WANT TO
KILL US?
LOOK, FELLA.
YOU--YOU TAKE A SIP
TOO MUCH OF THAT
OLD WOOD ALKY,
AND ALMOST ANYTHING
SEEMS LIKE IT--
WHERE?
WHERE ARE WE?
EARTH?
CONSTELLATIONS
SEEM RIGHT, BUT--
EXPLAIN!
EXPLAIN THIS TRICK.
I--I...
[DOG BARKING]
BIPED...
SMALL...
GOOD CRANIAL
DEVELOPMENT.
NO DOUBT,
CONSIDERABLE
HUMAN ANCESTRY.
IS THAT HOW
YOU'RE ABLE TO
FAKE ALL OF THIS?
VERY GOOD.
MODERN MUSEUM
PERFECTION...
RIGHT DOWN
TO THE CEMENT BEAMS.
VERY, VERY GOOD.
OH, I'D GIVE A LOT
TO SEE THE HOSPITAL.
PROBABLY...
NEEDLES AND...
SUTURES.
ALL THE PAIN.
THEY USED TO
HAND-CUT AND SEW PEOPLE
LIKE GARMENTS.
NEEDLES AND SUTURES...
ALL THE TERRIBLE PAIN!
HOW LONG BEFORE WE GET
A FULL ANSWER?
I'LL NEED AT LEAST
TWO MORE DAYS
BEFORE I DARE MAKE
ANOTHER ATTEMPT.
McCOY COULD HAVE BEEN
IN THE CITY A WEEK NOW
FOR ALL WE KNOW,
AND WHATEVER HE DOES
THAT AFFECTS HER
AND CHANGES HISTORY
COULD HAPPEN TONIGHT,
TOMORROW MORNING.
CAPTAIN, OUR LAST
BIT OF INFORMATION
WAS OBTAINED
AT THE EXPENSE
OF 30 HOURS' WORK
AND FUSED
AND BURNED CIRCUITS.
I MUST KNOW WHETHER SHE
LIVES OR DIES, SPOCK.
I MUST KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
Man: EXTREE, EXTREE.
GET YOUR MORNING PAPER!
EXTRA! PAPER!
READ ALL ABOUT IT!
OH, MISS...
THAT COFFEE, IT JUST
SMELLS WONDERFUL.
YOU LOOK TERRIBLE!
YOU BETTER SIT DOWN.
COME ON.
I CAN'T. I GOT
TO KEEP MOVING.
I CAN'T LET THEM
FIND ME.
THERE'S A COT
IN THE BACK ROOM.
THEY WON'T FIND YOU
THERE. COME ON.
THIS IS HOW HISTORY WENT
AFTER McCOY CHANGED IT.
HERE...
THE LATE 1930s--
A GROWING PACIFIST MOVEMENT
WHOSE INFLUENCE DELAYED
THE UNITED STATES' ENTRY
INTO THE SECOND WORLD WAR.
WHILE PEACE NEGOTIATIONS
DRAGGED ON,
GERMANY HAD TIME TO COMPLETE
ITS HEAVY-WATER EXPERIMENTS.
GERMANY--
FASCISM, HITLER.
SIEG...
HEIL!
SIEG HEIL!
WON THE SECOND
WORLD WAR...
BECAUSE ALL THIS
LETS THEM DEVELOP
THE A-BOMB FIRST.
THERE'S NO MISTAKE,
CAPTAIN.
LET ME RUN IT AGAIN.
EDITH KEELER, FOUNDER
OF THE PEACE MOVEMENT.
BUT SHE WAS RIGHT.
PEACE WAS THE WAY.
SHE WAS RIGHT,
BUT AT THE WRONG TIME.
WITH THE A-BOMB,
AND WITH THEIR
V-2 ROCKETS
TO CARRY THEM,
GERMANY CAPTURED
THE WORLD.
NO.
AND ALL THIS
BECAUSE McCOY CAME BACK
AND SOMEHOW
KEPT HER FROM DYING
IN A STREET ACCIDENT,
AS SHE WAS MEANT TO.
WE MUST STOP HIM, JIM.
HOW DID SHE DIE?
WHAT DAY?
I CAN ESTIMATE
GENERAL HAPPENINGS
FROM THESE IMAGES,
BUT I CAN'T TRACE
DOWN PRECISE ACTIONS
AT EXACT MOMENTS,
CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY.
SPOCK...
I BELIEVE...
I'M IN LOVE
WITH EDITH KEELER.
JIM, EDITH KEELER
MUST DIE.
HEY, NOW. COME ON.
YOU'RE NOT READY
TO TAKE ON
ANY TIGERS JUST YET.
LIE DOWN.
THE MOST COMMON QUESTION
TO ASK WOULD BE,
WHERE AM I?
I DON'T THINK
I'LL ASK IT.
WHY NOT?
THE ONLY POSSIBLE ANSWER
WOULD CONCLUSIVELY
PROVE THAT I'M...
EITHER UNCONSCIOUS
OR DEMENTED.
THIS LOOKS
LIKE OLD EARTH
AROUND 1920 OR '25.
WOULD YOU CARE
TO TRY FOR '30?
I AM UNCONSCIOUS...
OR DEMENTED.
I HAVE A FRIEND THAT TALKS
ABOUT EARTH
THE SAME WAY
THAT YOU DO.
WOULD YOU
LIKE TO MEET HIM?
I'M A SURGEON,
NOT A PSYCHIATRIST.
I AM LEONARD McCOY,
SENIOR MEDICAL
OFFICER ABOARD
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
I DON'T MEAN
TO DISBELIEVE YOU,
BUT THAT'S HARDLY
A NAVY UNIFORM.
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT.
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT,
DEAR...
BECAUSE I DON'T BELIEVE
IN YOU, EITHER.
GET SOME REST.
EDITH.
ARE YOU
FOLLOWING ME, SIR?
WITH ULTERIOR
MOTIVES.
DOES THAT
PLEASE YOU?
I HOPE
IT MEANS WHAT--OH!
HOW STUPID! I'VE BEEN
UP AND DOWN THOSE STAIRS
A THOUSAND TIMES.
I COULD HAVE
BROKEN MY NECK.
CAPTAIN, I DID NOT
PLAN TO EAVESDROP.
NO, OF COURSE
YOU DIDN'T.
I MUST POINT OUT THAT
WHEN SHE STUMBLED...
SHE MIGHT HAVE DIED
RIGHT THERE,
HAD YOU NOT CAUGHT HER.
IT'S NOT YET TIME.
McCOY ISN'T HERE.
WE'RE NOT THAT SURE
OF OUR FACTS.
WHO'S TO SAY WHEN
THE EXACT TIME
WILL COME?
SAVE HER--
DO AS YOUR HEART
TELLS YOU TO DO--
AND MILLIONS WILL DIE
WHO DID NOT DIE BEFORE.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
COME IN.
WELL, YOU LOOK
JUST FINE, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT LIKE
TO SEE THE EVENING PAPER.
NO,
NOT PARTICULARLY.
YOU KNOW, I'VE
CONVINCED MYSELF
THAT THIS IS ALL
IN A CORDRUZINE
HALLUCINATION,
BUT I'VE DECIDED
YOU'RE NOT.
THAT'S REASSURING.
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT,
WHAT ARE YOU?
A FRIEND.
WHEN YOU SHOWED UP HERE,
YOU LOOKED LIKE
YOU COULD USE ONE.
I DON'T DOUBT IT.
WHAT ABOUT THIS PLACE?
YOU RUN IT?
I TRY TO.
WHY?
IT'S NECESSARY.
WELL, IT WAS FOR ME,
AT LEAST.
YOU MAY HAVE SAVED
MY LIFE.
LOTS OF PEOPLE
DRINK FROM THE WRONG
BOTTLE SOMETIMES.
NOT AS WRONG
AS THE BOTTLE
I DRANK FROM.
ALLOW ME TO SHOW
MY GRATITUDE.
PERHAPS
THERE'S SOMETHING I
CAN DO AROUND HERE
TO THANK YOU.
WE CAN TALK
ABOUT THAT LATER.
I HAVE TO GO.
MY YOUNG MAN IS TAKING ME
TO A CLARK GABLE MOVIE.
A WHO MOVIE?
A CARK GABLE--
DON'T YOU KNOW?
WELL, I KNOW WHAT
A MOVIE IS, BUT...
THAT'S VERY STRANGE.
YOU GET SOME REST.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
[HORN HONKS]
[HONK HONK]
IF WE HURRY,
MAYBE WE CAN CATCH
THE CLARK GABLE MOVIE
AT THE ORPHEUM.
WHAT?
YOU KNOW, DR. McCOY SAID
THE SAME THING.
McCOY!
LEONARD McCOY?
WELL...YES.
HE'S IN THE MISSION.
HE'S--
STAY RIGHT HERE.
SPOCK!
STAY RIGHT THERE!
WHAT IS IT?
McCOY! HE'S--
JIM!
BONES!
NO, JIM!
EDITH!
[TIRES SCREECH]
AAH!
YOU DELIBERATELY
STOPPED ME, JIM.
I COULD HAVE
SAVED HER.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU JUST DID?
HE KNOWS, DOCTOR.
HE KNOWS.
WHAT HAPPENED, SIR?
YOU ONLY LEFT
A MOMENT AGO.
WE WERE SUCCESSFUL.
TIME HAS RESUMED
ITS SHAPE.
ALL IS
AS IT WAS BEFORE.
MANY SUCH JOURNEYS
ARE POSSIBLE.
LET ME BE YOUR GATEWAY.
CAPTAIN,
THE ENTERPRISE
IS UP THERE.
THEY'RE ASKING
IF WE WANT
TO BEAM UP.
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.