ANYTHING, LIEUTENANT?
NO, SIR.
I'VE TRIED EVERY MAJOR
TRANSMITTING STATION
ON DENEVA.
NONE OF THEM
HAVE ACKNOWLEDGED
MY CONTACT SIGNAL.
TRY GSK-783,
SUBSPACE FREQUENCY 3.
SIR, THAT'S A CALL SIGN
FOR A PRIVATE TRANSMITTER.
I'M VERY WELL AWARE
OF THAT, LIEUTENANT.
TRY IT.
YES, SIR.
EVALUATION,
MR. SPOCK.
AS I SPECULATED, CAPTAIN,
THE OVERALL PATTERN
OF MASS INSANITY
DESTROYING CIVILIZATIONS
FOLLOWS AN ALMOST
STRAIGHT LINE
THROUGH THIS SECTION
OF THE GALAXY.
OVER HERE
THE BETA PORTILIN SYSTEM--
THE ANCIENT CIVILIZATIONS.
ARCHAEOLOGISTS HAVE
GIVEN US INFORMATION
INDICATING THAT THEY
WERE THE BEGINNING.
200 YEARS AGO,
LAVINIUS 5 WAS SWEPT
BY MASS INSANITY,
THEN PHETA SIGNI 12.
THE LAST WAS INGRIAM B,
TWO YEARS AGO.
AND NEXT IN LINE--
DENEVA.
BONES, WHAT'S
YOUR THEORY
ABOUT THE CAUSE
OF ALL THIS?
THERE IS NO MEDICAL
OR SCIENTIFIC CAUSE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED
ON THOSE PLANETS,
JIM.
BUT IT FOLLOWS
A DEFINITE PATTERN--
A SYSTEMATIC PROGRESSION
FROM PLANET TO PLANET.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE PICKING UP
A SHIP ON
OUR SENSORS,
HEADING
DIRECTLY INTO
THE DENEVAN SUN.
HE'LL BURN UP.
PLOT AN INTERCEPTION
COURSE, MR. SULU,
WARP FACTOR 8.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TRY TO CONTACT THAT SHIP.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
SHIP IS A ONE-MAN VESSEL
OF DENEVAN CONFIGURATION,
CAPTAIN.
HE DOES NOT SEEM TO BE
OUT OF CONTROL.
HIS COURSE IS
STRAIGHT FOR THE SUN.
SCOTTY, TRACTOR BEAMS?
OUT OF RANGE, SIR.
Uhura:
MAKING CONTACT, CAPTAIN.
DENEVAN SHIP, THIS IS
THE "U.S.S. ENTERPRISE."
CAN YOU
REVERSE YOUR COURSE?
ACKNOWLEDGE.
[STATIC]
CAPTAIN,
WE'LL GET TOO
CLOSE TO THE SUN.
KEEP CLOSING.
DENEVAN SHIP,
REVERSE YOUR COURSE.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
REVERSE YOUR COURSE!
ACKNOWLEDGE.
[STATIC]
OUTER HULL TEMPERATURE
NOW 480 DEGREES AND RISING.
HE'S TOO CLOSE,
CAPTAIN.
SO ARE WE.
HULL TEMPERATURE
1,000 DEGREES AND RISING.
THE SUN'S GRAVIMETRIC
PULL INCREASING.
Denevan pilot: I DID IT!
IT'S FINALLY GONE!
I'M FREE!
I'M--
HE BURNED UP,
CAPTAIN.
REVERSE COURSE.
180 DEGREES ABOUT.
AYE, SIR.
ALL CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
HULL TEMPERATURE FALLING,
GRAVIMETRIC PULL
APPROACHING
TOLERANCE LEVEL.
VERY WELL.
REDUCE TO
SUBWARP SPEED.
TAKE US TO DENEVA.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
THAT DENEVAN SHIP
HEADED DELIBERATELY
INTO THE SUN. WHY?
THERE'S ONE POSSIBILITY.
THE MASS INSANITY
MAY HAVE REACHED
THIS PLANET, TOO.
CAPTAIN, I'M HAVING
DIFFICULTY ON THAT
TRANSMITTER CALL TO DENEVA.
KEEP TRYING.
YES, SIR.
JIM, YOUR BROTHER SAM,
HIS FAMILY,
AREN'T THEY STATIONED
ON THIS PLANET?
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3287.2.
THE MASS INSANITY
WE HAVE TRACKED ACROSS
THIS SECTION OF THE GALAXY
SEEMS TO HAVE
ALREADY TOUCHED DENEVA.
THAT PLANET,
COLONIZED OVER A CENTURY AGO,
IS ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL IN THE GALAXY.
PLANET DEVELOPMENT
IS NORMAL, CAPTAIN.
ORIGINALLY COLONIZED
AS A FREIGHTING LINE
BASE IN THIS AREA.
AYE. THEY MAKE REGULAR
TRIPS FROM HERE
CARRYING SUPPLIES
TO THE ASTEROID BELT
FOR THE MINERS
AND BRINGING CARGO OUT.
I'VE MADE
THE RUN A COUPLE
OF TIMES MYSELF
AS AN ENGINEERING ADVISOR.
NO FEDERATION CONTACTS
FOR OVER A YEAR.
CAPTAIN.
I'VE MADE CONTACT
WITH YOUR PRIVATE
TRANSMITTER, SIR.
PUT IT ON AUDIO.
Woman:
PLEASE HURRY.
HELP US.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME.
THEY'LL KNOW.
PLEASE!
PLEASE HELP US--
AURELAN, THIS IS JIM
ON THE "ENTERPRISE."
REPEAT YOUR MESSAGE.
CONTACT BROKEN, SIR.
RE-ESTABLISH.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I'M NOT INTERESTED IN
YOUR EXCUSES, LIEUTENANT.
RE-ESTABLISH CONTACT
WITH THAT TRANSMITTER.
I'M AFRAID
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE AT
THE MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
THEY STOPPED
BROADCASTING
IMMEDIATELY.
THEY DO NOT
ACKNOWLEDGE MY
CONTACT SIGNAL.
KEEP TRYING
TO RAISE THEM.
YES, SIR.
JIM, DID
YOU KNOW WHO
THAT WOMAN WAS?
YES.
YOU WERE RIGHT
A WHILE BACK.
MY BROTHER SAM
LIVES ON DENEVA.
HE'S A RESEARCH BIOLOGIST.
THAT WOMAN...
SOUNDED LIKE
HIS WIFE AURELAN.
SET YOUR PHASERS
ON STUN.
WE'RE GOING TO BEAM
DIRECTLY INTO
THE CAPITAL CITY.
ALERT STATUS.
MR. SPOCK.
LIEUTENANT UHURA HAS HAD
NO FURTHER RESPONSE
TO OUR SIGNALS.
SENSORS REPORT
THE EXPECTED NUMBER
OF HUMANS
ON THE PLANET SURFACE.
HOWEVER, THEY ARE
STRANGELY QUIET.
VERY LITTLE ACTIVITY.
I'LL WANT
A COMPLETE TRANSCRIPT
OF EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENS
DOWN THERE, YEOMAN.
YES, SIR.
LET'S GO.
ENERGIZE.
THERE ARE ALMOST
A MILLION INHABITANTS
OF DENEVA.
THERE'S
MORE THAN 100,000
IN THIS CITY ALONE.
WHERE IS EVERYONE?
THEY'RE HERE, CAPTAIN.
IN THE BUILDINGS.
STRANGELY QUIESCENT.
MY BROTHER'S LAB
IS OVER THERE.
THEY SIGNALED US ONCE.
THERE SHOULD BE
SOMEONE THERE.
LET'S FIND OUT
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
[SHOUTING]
CAPTAIN, SEVERAL PEOPLE
APPROACHING.
GO BACK!
GET AWAY!
WE DON'T WANT
TO HURT YOU!
GO BACK!
GET OUT OF HERE.
GO ON, GET AWAY!
GO AWAY!
GET OUT OF HERE!
WE DON'T WANT
TO HURT YOU.
STAND BY TO FIRE.
FIRE.
DID YOU HEAR
WHAT THEY SAID,
MR. SPOCK?
INDEED.
THEY SEEMED
MOST CONCERNED
FOR OUR SAFETY.
THEY TRIED TO BRAIN US
WITH THESE CLUBS.
CHECK THEM OUT, BONES.
THEIR ATTITUDE
WAS INCONSISTENT
WITH THEIR ACTIONS.
TO SAY THE LEAST.
THERE'S SOMETHING
WRONG, JIM.
THEIR NERVOUS SYSTEMS--
UNCONSCIOUS LIKE THIS,
THERE SHOULD BE
JUST ROUTINE
AUTONOMIC ACTIVITY,
BUT I'M GETTING
A VERY HIGH READING.
AS THOUGH, EVEN IN
THEIR UNCONSCIOUS STATE,
THEY'RE BEING
VIOLENTLY STIMULATED.
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
FAN OUT.
FOLLOW ME.
AAH!
SECURITY.
AAH! THEY'RE HERE!
THEY'RE HERE!
PLEASE! KEEP THEM AWAY!
[SOBBING]
THEY'RE HERE!
BONES.
[SOBBING SUBSIDES]
AURELAN,
YOU'RE SAFE NOW.
IS THIS YOUR
BROTHER, JIM?
OHH.
SAM.
IT IS MY BROTHER.
WAS MY BROTHER.
I'M SORRY, JIM.
THE BOY'S UNCONSCIOUS,
BUT HE'S STILL ALIVE.
PETER.
I BETTER GET
THE BOY AND THE MOTHER
BACK TO THE SHIP, JIM.
I CAN'T DO MUCH
FOR THEM DOWN HERE.
GET READY TO BEAM UP.
CALLING
"ENTERPRISE."
PREPARE TO BEAM UP
PARTY OF 4.
CAPTAIN, I UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU MUST--
YES. YES, MR. SPOCK.
YOU HEARD
MY SISTER-IN-LAW
SAY SOMETHING ABOUT
"THEY" BEING HERE.
YOUR GUESS.
NOTICE THE VENTILATOR,
CAPTAIN.
APPARENTLY THEY
WERE TRYING TO KEEP
SOMETHING OUTSIDE
FROM GETTING IN.
OBVIOUSLY THEY WERE NOT
ENTIRELY SUCCESSFUL.
IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
THERE ARE NO HARMFUL
LIFE FORMS REPORTED.
OUR SENSORS DIDN'T
PICK UP ANYTHING
THAT DIDN'T BELONG HERE.
THAT IS CORRECT.
I AM AT A LOSS
TO UNDERSTAND IT.
READY TO BEAM UP,
CAPTAIN.
I'D LIKE YOU
TO BE ONBOARD
WHEN YOUR SISTER-IN-LAW
REGAINS CONSCIOUSNESS.
TAKE CHARGE OF
THE LANDING PARTY,
MR. SPOCK.
I WANT SOME ANSWERS
TO ALL THIS.
I WON'T BE ABLE TO
GIVE YOU THE EXACT CAUSE
UNTIL I GET THE PLATES
BACK FROM THE LAB.
THEY'RE BOTH
IN EXTREME PAIN.
I SEDATED THEM HEAVILY.
BUT YOUR SISTER-IN-LAW
SEEMS TO HAVE
A HIGH TOLERANCE.
THE TRANQUILIZER HASN'T
AFFECTED HER MUCH.
CAN SHE TALK?
YES.
[MOANING]
AURELAN.
IT'S JIM.
JIM?
SAM, HE'S--
HE'S DEAD.
BUT YOUR SON'S
STILL ALIVE.
YOU'VE GOT
TO HELP US.
YOU ARE HERE.
IT IS YOU, JIM.
YES, I'M HERE.
YOU HAVE TO TELL US
WHAT HAPPENED, AURELAN,
TO YOU AND THE OTHERS.
THEY CAME...
8 MONTHS AGO.
WHO?
THINGS.
HORRIBLE THINGS!
VISITORS
BROUGHT THEM
IN THEIR VESSEL
FROM ANOTHER PLANET.
EGRABIE.
WHAT KIND OF THINGS?
NOT THE SHIP'S CREW'S
FAULT.
THE THINGS MADE THEM
BRING THEIR SHIP HERE.
AURELAN...
IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT YOU TELL US
WHAT KINDS OF THINGS?
NOT THEIR FAULT.
[SOBBING LOUDLY]
WHEN SHE ANSWERS
QUESTIONS,
ANY QUESTIONS,
IT'S AS IF
SHE'S FIGHTING
TO GET THE ANSWERS OUT,
AS THOUGH SOMETHING
IS EXERTING PAIN
TO STOP HER.
THEY USE IT
TO CONTROL US.
THEY'RE
SPREADING, JIM.
THEY NEED US TO BE
THEIR ARMS AND LEGS.
THEY'RE FORCING US
TO BUILD SHIPS
FOR THEM.
DON'T LET THEM!
DON'T LET THEM
GO ANY FURTHER!
AAH!
MY BROTHER'S SON?
I'LL DO EVERYTHING
I CAN, JIM, TO SAVE HIM.
REPORT.
THE STREETS
ARE EXTRAORDINARILY
QUIET, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE SEEN
NO OTHER DENEVANS,
AND THE ONES
WE STUNNED EARLIER
WERE GONE WHEN
WE CAME OUT.
YOU'VE SEEN SOME
KIND OF CREATURE?
ANY ALIEN FORM?
NONE, SIR.
JUST THAT NOISE
WE HEARD.
A PECULIAR
BUZZING SOUND.
WE WERE ABOUT
TO INVESTIGATE IT.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO FIND
OUT WHAT IT IS.
SET YOUR PHASERS ON
FORCE 3, TO KILL.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR SOME KIND
OF CREATURE,
AND WE ALREADY KNOW
IT WILL KILL.
[BUZZING]
[SQUEAK]
[BUZZING CONTINUES]
SPOCK!
[SQUEAK]
FORM A RING.
FIRE!
INCREDIBLE. NOT ONLY
SHOULD IT HAVE BEEN
DESTROYED BY OUR PHASERS,
IT DOES NOT EVEN REGISTER
ON MY TRICORDER.
CAPTAIN, IT DOESN'T
EVEN LOOK REAL.
IT IS NOT LIFE AS
WE KNOW OR UNDERSTAND IT.
YET IT IS OBVIOUSLY ALIVE,
IT EXISTS.
AND IT CAN BEAR UP
UNDER FULL PHASER POWER.
CAPTAIN, I SUGGEST
WE RISK TAKING IT ABOARD.
IT'S TOO CLOSE
IN HERE.
IT MAY BE A TRAP.
LET'S MOVE OUT.
SPOCK!
IT'S GONE.
CAN YOU STAND?
SPOCK,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG
SUPPLEMENTAL.
WHATEVER THE CREATURES ARE,
THEY HAVE APPARENTLY TAKEN OVER
ALL THE INHABITANTS OF DENEVA.
MEANWHILE, SHIP'S SURGEON
DR. McCOY
IS EXAMINING
A STRANGE PUNCTURE WOUND
LEFT BY ONE OF THE CREATURES
ON MR. SPOCK'S BACK.
NURSE.
THAT'S THE SECOND TIME
HE'S COME OUT OF IT.
EITHER HE'S FIGHTING US,
OR SOMETHING INSIDE
OF HIM IS FIGHTING US.
DOCTOR, THE READINGS HAVE
NEVER LOOKED LIKE THAT BEFORE,
NOT EVEN ON MR. SPOCK.
LET'S PREPARE TO CLOSE.
NURSE!
DOCTOR, THAT'S NOT ALL
YOU'RE GOING TO DO.
MISS CHAPEL.
DOCTOR, THERE IS
MORE OF IT IN HIM,
ENTWINED ALL THROUGH
HIS BODY.
MISS CHAPEL, IF YOU
CANNOT ASSIST ME
AS REQUIRED,
CALL ANOTHER NURSE
IN HERE.
BUT DO ONE
OR THE OTHER NOW.
HOW IS HE?
TO BE VERY FRANK, JIM,
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I CAN DO ANYTHING
FOR SPOCK OR YOUR NEPHEW.
THEY'RE PIECES OF SOME FORM
OF LIVING TISSUE.
I REMOVED ONE
FROM SPOCK'S SPINAL CORD,
THE OTHER FROM YOUR
SISTER-IN-LAW'S BODY.
THEY'RE BOTH THE SAME.
THE BOY'S FAR
TOO WEAK TO TOUCH.
BESIDES, REMOVAL
OF THE TISSUE
WOULDN'T STOP THE PAIN
ANYHOW, AS FAR AS
I CAN TELL.
DID YOU OPERATE
ON SPOCK IN TIME?
NO. I JUST REMOVED THESE
FOR EXAMINATION.
HIS BODY'S
FULL OF THESE TENTACLES,
ENTWINING
AND GROWING ALL ABOUT
HIS NERVOUS SYSTEM.
MY NEPHEW?
THE SAME.
EVIDENTLY,
WHEN THE CREATURE ATTACKS,
IT LEAVES A STINGER
MUCH LIKE A BEE OR WASP,
LEAVING ONE OF THESE
IN THE VICTIM'S BODY.
IT TAKES OVER THE VICTIM
VERY RAPIDLY,
AND THE ENTWINING
IS FAR, FAR TOO INVOLVED
FOR CONVENTIONAL SURGERY
TO REMOVE.
RECOMMENDATIONS?
I'M SORRY, JIM.
THE LAB,
THE SCIENCE DEPARTMENTS...
WE'RE ALL STUMPED.
NO!
MR. SPOCK.
NO, I WON'T.
MR. SPOCK--OH!
BRIDGE,
THIS IS SICK BAY.
TELL DR. McCOY
MR. SPOCK
JUST LEFT HERE.
HE'S DELIRIOUS AND
POSSIBLY DANGEROUS.
ALL DECKS,
SECURITY ALERT.
LOCATE AND RESTRAIN
MR. SPOCK.
HE MAY BE DANGEROUS.
USE PHASERS ON STUN
IF NECESSARY.
MUST TAKE SHIP--
DOWN!
I MUST...
TAKE IT DOWN.
GET HIM BACK TO THE SICK BAY.
USE SECURITY RESTRAINTS.
THE K-3 INDICATOR
REGISTERS THE LEVEL OF PAIN.
NOW WATCH IT
AS I TURN IT ON.
THAT'S WHAT HE'S
BEEN GOING THROUGH.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
NO WONDER
THE POOR DEVILS
GO MAD.
DR. McCOY.
CAPTAIN.
SPOCK.
THESE RESTRAINTS WILL
NO LONGER BE NECESSARY.
NOR WILL
YOUR SEDATIVES, DOCTOR.
I'LL BE ABLE
TO RETURN TO DUTY.
I APOLOGIZE
FOR MY WEAKNESS EARLIER
WHEN I TRIED TO TAKE
CONTROL OF THE SHIP.
I SIMPLY
DID NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHAT IS THERE
TO UNDERSTAND,
MR. SPOCK?
I AM A VULCAN, DOCTOR.
PAIN IS A THING
OF THE MIND.
THE MIND CAN BE CONTROLLED.
YOU'RE ONLY HALF VULCAN.
WHAT ABOUT
THE HUMAN HALF?
IT IS PROVING TO BE
AN INCONVENIENCE,
BUT IT IS MANAGEABLE.
THE CREATURE, WITH ALL
OF ITS THOUSANDS OF PARTS,
EVEN NOW IS PRESSURING ME.
IT WANTS THIS SHIP,
BUT I AM RESISTING.
CAN HE CONTROL IT
THE WAY HE SAYS, BONES?
WHO KNOWS, JIM?
I KNOW
THE AMOUNT OF PAIN
THE CREATURE CAN
INFLICT UPON HIM,
BUT WHETHER
HE CAN CONTROL IT
HOUR TO HOUR...
I HAVE MY OWN WILL,
CAPTAIN.
LET ME HELP.
I NEED YOU, SPOCK...
BUT WE CAN'T
TAKE ANY CHANCES.
WE'LL KEEP YOU...
CONFINED
FOR A WHILE LONGER.
IF YOU CAN
MAINTAIN CONTROL,
WE'LL SEE.
UHH...
MY NEPHEW.
IF HE REGAINS
CONSCIOUSNESS,
WILL HE GO
THROUGH THAT?
YES.
HELP THEM.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT IT TAKES OR COSTS.
YOU'VE GOT TO HELP THEM.
JIM, AREN'T YOU
FORGETTING SOMETHING?
THERE ARE
OVER A MILLION COLONISTS
ON THAT PLANET
DOWN THERE
JUST AS MUCH
YOUR RESPONSIBILITY.
THEY NEED
YOUR HELP, TOO.
I AM A VULCAN.
THERE IS NO PAIN.
MR. SPOCK. I THOUGHT
YOU WERE STILL CONFINED
TO SICK BAY.
I WAS.
HERE, NOW.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
I HAVE AN ERRAND
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
YOU WILL BEAM ME DOWN
TO THE SAME COORDINATES
AS BEFORE.
NOT LIKELY,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS AN ORDER,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
AND I'M SORRY
I HAVE TO DISOBEY IT.
THE CAPTAIN SAID NO ONE
WAS TO TRANSPORT DOWN.
MR. SPOCK.
FREEZE RIGHT THERE,
MR. SPOCK,
OR I'LL PUT YOU
TO SLEEP FOR SURE.
THIS IS MR. SCOTT
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
GET ME THE CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK, I GAVE YOU
AN ORDER TO STAY
IN THE SICK BAY.
UNTIL THE PAIN
WAS GONE, CAPTAIN.
IT HAS BEEN
DISCONTINUED...BY ME.
SCOTTY.
HE SAID HE WAS TRANSPORTING
DOWN TO THE SURFACE, SIR.
YOUR ORDERS WERE THAT
NO ONE WAS TO BEAM DOWN
UNLESS YOU AUTHORIZED IT,
AND KNOWING MISTER SPOCK'S
DETERMINATION ON SOME THINGS,
I THOUGHT I'D BETTER HOLD HIM
HERE UNTIL I GOT YOUR ORDERS.
ONE OF THE CREATURES
WILL HAVE TO BE CAPTURED
AND ANALYZED, CAPTAIN.
WE DID NOT HAVE
A CLEAR OPPORTUNITY
TO DO SO EARLIER
WHEN I WAS ATTACKED.
SINCE MY NERVOUS SYSTEM
IS ALREADY AFFECTED,
AS YOU POINTED OUT,
DOCTOR,
I DON'T BELIEVE THEY
CAN DO MUCH MORE TO ME.
JIM, THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I DON'T WANT MY PATIENTS
RUNNING AROUND.
HE SHOULD BE IN BED.
I AM IN COMPLETE CONTROL
OF MYSELF, DOCTOR.
THE FACT THAT I AM HERE
PROVES THAT I DO NOT
BELONG IN BED.
MR. SPOCK...
YOUR LOGIC, AS USUAL,
IS INESCAPABLE.
BEAM HIM DOWN.
STAY IN CONSTANT
TOUCH WITH US.
GIVE HIM YOUR PHASER.
HE'LL NEED THAT, TOO.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
ENERGIZE.
JIM, THAT MAN IS SICK.
DON'T GIVE ME
ANY DAMNABLE LOGIC
ABOUT HIM BEING
THE ONLY MAN
FOR THE JOB.
I DON'T HAVE TO, BONES.
WE BOTH KNOW HE IS.
[BUZZING]
[SQUEAK SQUEAK]
COME IN, GENTLEMEN.
I BELIEVE YOU'LL
FIND THIS INTERESTING.
DOCTOR, YOUR MEDICAL
SKILL AND CURIOSITY
ARE QUITE ADMIRABLE,
BUT I ASSURE YOU
I'M ALL RIGHT.
YOU MAY BE
CONTROLLING
THE PAIN, MR. SPOCK,
BUT YOU'RE FAR
FROM ALL RIGHT.
UNIMPORTANT
AT THE MOMENT, DOCTOR.
PLEASE OBSERVE.
INTERESTING, GENTLEMEN.
A ONE-CELLED CREATURE
RESEMBLING, MORE THAN
ANYTHING ELSE,
A HUGE, INDIVIDUAL
BRAIN CELL.
YES. THAT WOULD ANSWER
A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND WHAT
I'M SUGGESTING, CAPTAIN?
I THINK SO.
THIS MAY BE ONE CELL
IN A LARGER ORGANISM,
AN INCREDIBLY HUGE ORGANISM,
IN FACT.
AND ALTHOUGH IT IS NOT
PHYSICALLY CONNECTED
TO THE OTHER CELLS,
IT IS, NEVERTHELESS,
PART OF THE WHOLE CREATURE,
GUIDED BY THE WHOLE,
DRAWING ITS STRENGTH
FROM THE WHOLE,
WHICH PROBABLY ACCOUNTS
FOR ITS UNUSUAL RESISTANCE
TO OUR PHASER WEAPONS.
EXISTING SO DIFFERENTLY
FROM ANY LIVING MATTER
OR ENERGY AS WE KNOW IT,
THAT IT MAY HAVE COME HERE
PLANET BY PLANET
FROM AN ENTIRELY
DIFFERENT GALAXY.
FROM A PLACE WHERE
OUR PHYSICAL LAWS
DO NOT APPLY.
WE MAY THEREFORE
FIND IT DIFFICULT
TO DESTROY, CAPTAIN.
BUT NOT IMPOSSIBLE,
MR. SPOCK.
THE DENEVAN
THAT FLEW INTO THE SUN
CRIED OUT THAT HE WAS FREE,
THAT HE'D WON.
THAT'S THE ANGLE
TO WORK ON, GENTLEMEN.
I WANT AN ANALYSIS
OF ALL THIS
FROM MEDICAL AND
LIFE SCIENCE DEPARTMENTS
WITHIN THE HOUR.
YES, SIR.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I'VE TRIED EVERYTHING I CAN.
VARIANT RADIATION,
INTENSE HEAT EVEN AS GREAT
AS 9,000 DEGREES.
THEN YOU'RE
WASTING YOUR TIME.
THERE HAS TO BE
SOMETHING THAT'LL
KILL THE CREATURE
WITHOUT DESTROYING
THE HUMAN HOST.
WHICH HAPPENS
TO BE MY POINT.
THE THING WON'T DIE,
EVEN AT TEMPERATURES
AND RADIATION
WHICH WOULD BURN SPOCK
AND YOUR NEPHEW TO ASHES.
I CAN'T
ACCEPT THAT, BONES.
WE'VE GOT 14 SCIENCE
LABS ABOARD THIS SHIP.
THE FINEST EQUIPMENT AND
COMPUTERS IN THE GALAXY.
CAPTAIN...
I UNDERSTAND
YOUR CONCERN--
YOUR AFFECTION
FOR SPOCK,
THE FACT
THAT YOUR NEPHEW
IS THE LAST SURVIVOR
OF YOUR BROTHER'S
FAMILY.
NO, NO, BONES.
THERE'S MORE THAN
TWO LIVES AT STAKE HERE.
I CANNOT LET IT SPREAD
BEYOND THIS COLONY,
EVEN IF IT MEANS
DESTROYING
A MILLION PEOPLE
DOWN THERE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3289.8.
I AM FACED
WITH THE MOST DIFFICULT
DECISION OF MY LIFE.
UNLESS WE FIND A WAY
TO DESTROY THE CREATURES
WITHOUT KILLING
THEIR HUMAN HOSTS,
MY COMMAND RESPONSIBILITIES
WILL FORCE ME TO KILL
OVER A MILLION PEOPLE.
GENTLEMEN.
I REGRET I SEE NO OTHER
CHOICE FOR YOU, CAPTAIN.
WE ALREADY KNOW
THIS THING HAS DESTROYED
3 CIVILIZATIONS.
PERHAPS MORE.
GENTLEMEN, I WANT
IT STOPPED, TOO,
BUT NOT AT THE COST
OF DESTROYING
OVER A MILLION
PEOPLE.
INCLUDING MYSELF, DOCTOR,
AND CAPTAIN KIRK'S
YOUNG NEPHEW.
UNDERSTANDABLY UPSETTING,
BUT ONCE IT SPREADS
PAST HERE,
THERE ARE DOZENS
OF COLONIES BEYOND
AND BILLIONS OF PEOPLE.
IF KILLING
5 PEOPLE SAVES 10,
IT'S A BARGAIN.
IS THAT YOUR SIMPLE
LOGIC, MISTER SPOCK?
I WILL ACCEPT NEITHER OF THOSE
ALTERNATIVES, GENTLEMEN.
I CANNOT LET THIS THING
EXPAND BEYOND THIS PLANET,
NOR DO I INTEND TO KILL
A MILLION OR MORE PEOPLE
TO STOP IT.
I WANT ANOTHER ANSWER.
I'M PUTTING YOU GENTLEMEN
THE HOT SEAT WITH ME.
I WANT
THAT THIRD ALTERNATIVE.
REPORT.
I'M SORRY, JIM.
WE'VE BEEN
OVER AND OVER IT,
WE'VE MADE EVERY
CONCEIVABLE TEST.
I THEREFORE
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO BEAM DOWN TO
THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
I ALSO SUGGEST YOUR NEPHEW
ACCOMPANY ME.
REQUEST DENIED.
CAPTAIN...
I DO NOT MAKE
THIS REQUEST LIGHTLY.
I DO NOT KNOW
HOW MUCH LONGER
I CAN HOLD OUT
AGAINST THE PAIN.
BUT I DO KNOW WHAT THE BOY
WILL GO THROUGH
SHOULD HE REGAIN
CONSCIOUSNESS.
REQUEST DENIED.
THERE MUST BE
ANOTHER ANSWER.
SOMETHING IN THE SUN
KILLED THAT THING
BEFORE THE DENEVAN DIED.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'VE TRIED...HEAT,
RADIATION.
WHAT OTHER QUALITIES
OR PROPERTIES
DOES THE SUN HAVE?
IT EXISTS
PHYSICALLY.
IT OCCUPIES SPACE,
IT HAS MASS,
THEREFORE, GRAVITY.
IT CONVERTS
MATTER TO ENERGY.
[PULSING]
JIM, WE'VE BEEN
THROUGH IT AND
THROUGH IT.
RADIATION,
HEAT...
BUT ONE OTHER THING
YOU HAVEN'T MENTIONED.
IT'S BRIGHT.
IT RADIATES
A BLINDING LIGHT
IF YOU'RE CLOSE ENOUGH.
NOTHING LETHAL
ABOUT LIGHT.
NOT TO US.
BUT DOWN ON THE SURFACE,
THE CREATURES
STAYED IN THE SHADOWS
FOR THE MOST PART.
SUPPOSE...
THEY WEREN'T
SIMPLY HIDING.
SUPPOSE THEY'RE
SENSITIVE TO LIGHT,
LIGHT, LIKE IN A SUN
CLOSE UP.
A POSSIBILITY.
YOU CAN'T MOVE DENEVA
CLOSER TO THE SUN, JIM.
NO, BUT YOU CAN
MOVE THE EQUIVALENT
OF THE SUN TO DENEVA!
MR. SPOCK?
YES. IN ESSENCE
IT CAN BE DONE--
A STRING OF SATELLITES
AROUND THE PLANET
WITH BURNING TRIMAGNESITE
AND TRITIUM.
[SIGH]
WELL, I CAN RIG
A TEST CUBICLE
IN A BIO LAB,
PUT OUR SPECIMEN
IN IT.
BUT I DON'T--
GOOD.
LET'S GET ON IT.
YOUR FIGURES ARE,
OF COURSE, ACCURATE.
OF COURSE.
THE LIGHT OF THE SUN
AT THE PROXIMITY
WHERE THE DENEVAN
DECLARED HIMSELF FREE
WAS 1 MILLION CANDLES
PER SQUARE INCH.
IF THIS WORKS,
THE SATELLITES WE ORBIT
WILL PRODUCE LIGHT
OF SUCH INTENSITY
THAT EVEN SOMEONE
IN A CLOSED, DARKENED AREA
WILL BE AFFECTED BY IT.
READY, DOCTOR.
PUT ON
YOUR MASKS.
COMPLETED.
IT WORKED!
WE CAN DO IT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
JIM? WE CAN DO IT!
IT WORKED. IN A LAB.
WITH THE CREATURE
EXPOSED TO EVERYTHING
WE CAN GIVE IT.
BUT WHAT ABOUT THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE INFECTED?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE TRIAL--
MAYBE? THERE'S NO TIME
FOR MAYBES, BONES.
WE NEED TO KNOW NOW.
BUT I'D HAVE TO
PUT A--
YES, WE'D HAVE TO PUT
SOMEONE WHO'S INFECTED
UNDER THAT LIGHT.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
OF THE RISK?
WE HAVE TO DUPLICATE
THE CONDITIONS
ON THE PLANET.
AND SPOCK...
Spock: CAPTAIN.
YOU'LL NEED A HOST
FOR THE NEXT STEP
IN THE TEST.
TO DETERMINE
WHETHER THE CREATURE
CAN BE DRIVEN
FROM THE BODY.
I AM THE LOGICAL CHOICE.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
1-MILLION CANDLELIGHT
PER SQUARE INCH
CAN DO
TO YOUR OPTIC NERVES?
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY,
BONES.
WE HAVE TO DUPLICATE
THE BRILLIANCE THAT EXISTED
AT THE MOMENT THE DENEVAN
DECLARED HIMSELF FREED.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL RIG UP
A PROTECTIVE PAIR
OF GOGGLES.
THERE'LL BE NONE ON
THE PLANET'S SURFACE, DOCTOR.
I AGREE COMPLETELY.
UNFORTUNATELY,
YOU'RE BOTH RIGHT.
IT'S THE ONLY THING
WE CAN DO.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
MR. SPOCK'S
THE BEST FIRST OFFICER
IN THE FLEET.
PROCEED.
COMPLETED.
SPOCK, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
THE CREATURE WITHIN ME
IS GONE.
I AM FREE OF IT...
AND THE PAIN.
I AM ALSO...
QUITE BLIND.
AN EQUITABLE TRADE,
DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
DOCTOR, THE RESULTS
OF THE FIRST TESTS
ON THE CREATURE'S REMAINS...
OH, NO.
WHAT IS IT?
I THREW THE TOTAL
SPECTRUM OF LIGHT
AT THE CREATURE.
IT WASN'T NECESSARY.
I DIDN'T
STOP TO THINK
THAT MORE THAN
ONE KIND OF LIGHT
MIGHT'VE KILLED IT.
INTERESTING.
JUST AS DOGS
ARE SENSITIVE
TO CERTAIN SOUNDS
WHICH HUMANS
CANNOT HEAR,
THESE CREATURES EVIDENTLY
ARE SENSITIVE TO LIGHT
WHICH WE CANNOT SEE.
ARE YOU TELLING ME...
THAT SPOCK NEED NOT
HAVE BEEN BLINDED?
I DIDN'T NEED TO THROW
THE BLINDING WHITE LIGHT
AT ALL, JIM.
SPOCK, I--
DOCTOR, IT WAS
MY SELECTION AS WELL.
IT IS DONE.
BONES.
TAKE CARE OF HIM.
COMPLETING
THE SEEDING ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
210 ULTRAVIOLET SATELLITES
NOW IN POSITION.
72 MILES ALTITUDE.
PERMANENT ORBIT
ABOUT THE PLANET.
GOOD. SCANNERS?
SCANNERS READY, SIR.
VERY WELL.
READY, HELM?
READY, CAPTAIN.
SATELLITE CONTROL,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
ENERGIZE ALL SATELLITES.
AFFIRMATIVE.
ALL SATELLITES
OPERATIVE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, RECEIVING MESSAGES
FROM OUR GROUND STATION.
REPORT.
THE THINGS ARE DYING, SIR.
IT'S WORKING.
SICK BAY.
McCOY HERE.
TELL SPOCK...
IT WORKED.
YES, CAPTAIN.
HE'LL BE HAPPY
TO HEAR THAT.
BONES...
IT WASN'T YOUR FAULT.
BONES.
YEOMAN, RECORD THIS
FOR STARFLEET COMMAND.
READY, SIR.
THE ALIEN CREATURES
ON DENEVA HAVE BEEN
DESTROYED--
CAPTAIN, LOOK.
MR. SPOCK.
Kirk:
SPOCK.
YOU CAN SEE.
THE BLINDNESS
WAS TEMPORARY, JIM.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
HIS OPTICAL NERVES
WHICH AREN'T THE SAME
AS A HUMAN'S.
AN HEREDITARY TRAIT,
CAPTAIN.
THE BRIGHTNESS
OF THE VULCAN SUN
HAS CAUSED THE DEVELOPMENT
OF AN INNER EYELID,
WHICH ACTS
AS A SHIELD AGAINST
HIGH-INTENSITY LIGHT.
TOTALLY INSTINCTIVE,
DOCTOR.
WE TEND TO IGNORE IT,
AS YOU IGNORE YOUR
OWN APPENDIX.
MR. SPOCK.
REGAINING EYESIGHT
WOULD BE AN EMOTIONAL
EXPERIENCE FOR MOST.
YOU, I PRESUME,
FELT NOTHING?
QUITE THE CONTRARY,
CAPTAIN.
I HAD A VERY
STRONG REACTION.
MY FIRST SIGHT
WAS THE FACE OF DR. McCOY
BENDING OVER ME.
'TIS A PITY
YOUR BRIEF BLINDNESS
DID NOT INCREASE
YOUR APPRECIATION
FOR BEAUTY,
MR. SPOCK.
IF YOU GENTLEMEN
ARE FINISHED,
WOULD YOU MIND
LAYING IN A COURSE
FOR STARBASE 10,
MR. SPOCK?
MY PLEASURE,
CAPTAIN.
UNUSUAL EYE ARRANGEMENT.
I MIGHT'VE KNOWN
HE'D TURN UP WITH
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
WHAT'S THAT,
DOCTOR?
I SAID, PLEASE DON'T
TELL SPOCK THAT I SAID
HE WAS THE BEST
FIRST OFFICER
IN THE FLEET.
WHY, THANK YOU,
DR. McCOY.
YOU'VE BEEN SO CONCERNED
ABOUT HIS VULCAN EYES,
DOCTOR.
YOU FORGOT ABOUT
HIS VULCAN EARS.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 1,
MR. SULU.
WARP FACTOR 1,
SIR.