OH, CAPTAIN.
GOT A MINUTE?
A MINUTE.
IT'S SPOCK.
HAVE YOU NOTICED
ANYTHING STRANGE
ABOUT HIM?
NO, NOTHING
IN PARTICULAR. WHY?
WELL, IT'S NOTHING
I CAN PINPOINT
WITHOUT AN EXAMINATION,
BUT HE'S BECOME
INCREASINGLY RESTIVE.
IF HE WERE NOT A VULCAN,
I'D ALMOST SAY NERVOUS.
AND FOR ANOTHER THING,
HE'S AVOIDING FOOD.
I CHECKED, AND HE HASN'T
EATEN AT ALL IN THREE DAYS.
THAT JUST SOUNDS
LIKE MR. SPOCK
IN ONE OF HIS
CONTEMPLATIVE
PHASES.
MISS CHAPEL.
DR. McCOY.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S THIS?
OH, UH...
OH! VULCAN
PLOMIK SOUP.
AND I'LL BET
YOU MADE IT, TOO.
YOU NEVER GIVE UP
HOPING, DO YOU?
WELL, UH, MR. SPOCK HASN'T
BEEN EATING, DOCTOR,
AND I--I JUST HAPPENED
TO NOTICE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
CARRY ON,
MISS CHAPEL.
BONES,
I'M A BUSY MAN.
JIM, WHEN I
SUGGESTED TO SPOCK
THAT IT WAS TIME
FOR HIS ROUTINE
CHECK-UP,
YOUR LOGICAL,
UNEMOTIONAL
FIRST OFFICER
TURNED TO ME
AND SAID,
"YOU WILL CEASE TO
PRY INTO MY PERSONAL
MATTERS, DOCTOR,
OR I SHALL CERTAINLY
BREAK YOUR NECK."
SPOCK SAID THAT?
Spock:
WHAT IS THIS?
Chapel: AAH!
DON'T KEEP PRYING!
IF I WANT ANYTHING
FROM YOU,
I'LL ASK FOR IT!
CAPTAIN, I SHOULD
LIKE TO REQUEST
A LEAVE OF ABSENCE
ON MY HOME PLANET.
ON OUR
PRESENT COURSE,
YOU CAN DIVERT
TO VULCAN
WITH A LOSS OF BUT
2.8 LIGHT DAYS.
SPOCK, WHAT THE DEVIL
IS THIS ALL ABOUT?
I HAVE MADE
MY REQUEST,
CAPTAIN.
ALL I REQUIRE
FROM YOU IS THAT
YOU ANSWER IT--
YES OR NO?
Captain Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
ALL RIGHT, SPOCK,
LET'S HAVE IT.
IT IS UNDIGNIFIED
FOR A WOMAN
TO PLAY SERVANT
TO A MAN
WHO IS NOT HERS.
I'M MORE INTERESTED
IN YOUR REQUEST
FOR SHORE LEAVE.
IN ALL THE YEARS--
YOU HAVE MY REQUEST,
CAPTAIN.
WILL YOU GRANT IT
OR NOT?
IN ALL THE YEARS
THAT I'VE KNOWN YOU,
YOU'VE NEVER ASKED
FOR A LEAVE OF ANY SORT.
IN FACT,
YOU'VE REFUSED THEM.
WHY NOW?
CAPTAIN, SURELY
I HAVE ENOUGH LEAVE
TIME ACCUMULATED.
AGREED, BUT THAT ISN'T
THE QUESTION, IS IT?
IF THERE'S A PROBLEM
OF SOME SORT--
ILLNESS IN THE FAMILY--
NO.
NOTHING OF THAT NATURE,
CAPTAIN.
THEN, SINCE WE'RE
HEADED FOR ALTAIR 6,
AND SINCE
THE SHORE FACILITIES
THERE ARE EXCELLENT--
NO! I MUST--
I WISH TO TAKE
MY LEAVE ON VULCAN.
SPOCK, I'M ASKING YOU...
WHAT'S WRONG?
I NEED...REST.
I'M ASKING YOU TO
ACCEPT THAT ANSWER.
BRIDGE...HELM.
Sulu: YES, CAPTAIN?
ALTER COURSE TO VULCAN,
INCREASE SPEED
TO WARP 4.
AYE, SIR.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I SUPPOSE MOST OF US
OVERLOOK THE FACT
THAT EVEN VULCANS
AREN'T INDESTRUCTIBLE.
NO.
WE'RE NOT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3372.7--
ON COURSE, ON SCHEDULE,
BOUND FOR ALTAIR 6
VIA VULCAN.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
SEEMS TO BE UNDER STRESS.
HE HAS REQUESTED AND
BEEN GRANTED SHORE LEAVE.
SHIP SURGEON McCOY HAS HIM
UNDER MEDICAL SURVEILLANCE.
CAPTAIN, SOMETHING'S
COMING IN ON THE
STARFLEET CHANNEL.
PRIORITY
ON URGENT, SIR.
PUT IT ON AUDIO
OVER HERE, LIEUTENANT.
MESSAGE COMPLETE, SIR.
SWITCHING OVER.
TO CAPTAIN, U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
FROM STAR FLEET SECTOR NINE--
INAUGURATION CEREMONIES
ALTAIR 6
HAVE BEEN ADVANCED
SEVEN SOLAR DAYS.
YOU ARE ORDERED TO ALTER
YOUR FLIGHT PLAN
AS FILED TO ACCOMMODATE,
BY ORDER OF KOMACK,
ADMIRAL, STARFLEET COMMAND.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT MESSAGE.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV,
COMPUTE COURSE
AND SPEED
NECESSARY
FOR COMPLIANCE.
WE'LL HAVE TO HEAD
DIRECTLY THERE AT, UH...
WARP 6, SIR.
INSUFFICIENT TIME
TO STOP OFF AT VULCAN.
HEAD DIRECTLY
FOR ALTAIR 6.
SAILOR'S LUCK,
MR. SPOCK.
OR, AS ONE OF
FINAGLE'S LAWS
PUTS IT--
"ANY HOME PORT
THE SHIP MAKES
WILL BE
SOMEBODY ELSE'S,
NOT MINE."
THE NEW PRESIDENT
OF ALTAIR 6
WANTS TO GET
HIMSELF LAUNCHED
A WEEK EARLY,
SO WE HAVE
TO BE THERE
A WEEK EARLY.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL SEE
THAT YOU GET
YOUR LEAVE
AS SOON AS
WE'RE FINISHED.
I...QUITE UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
BRIDGE, NAVIGATION.
NAVIGATION.
CHEKOV HERE.
MR. CHEKOV, HOW LATE
WILL WE ARRIVE
FOR THE CEREMONIES
IF WE INCREASE
SPEED TO MAXIMUM
AND DIVERT TO VULCAN
JUST LONG ENOUGH
TO DROP OFF MR. SPOCK?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
HOW FAR BEHIND SCHEDULE WILL
DIVERTING TO VULCAN PUT US?
WE'RE ON COURSE
FOR VULCAN, CAPTAIN,
AS MR. SPOCK ORDERED.
THANK YOU, MR. CHEKOV.
KIRK OUT.
MR. SPOCK.
COME WITH ME,
PLEASE.
DECK FIVE.
YOU CHANGED COURSE
FOR VULCAN, MR. SPOCK.
WHY?
CHANGED
THE COURSE?
DO YOU DENY IT?
NO. NO, BY NO MEANS,
CAPTAIN.
IT IS QUITE POSSIBLE.
THEN WHY DID YOU DO IT?
CAPTAIN, I ACCEPT,
ON YOUR WORD, THAT I DID IT,
BUT I DO NOT KNOW WHY,
NOR DO I REMEMBER DOING IT.
CAPTAIN,
LOCK ME AWAY.
I DO NOT WISH
TO BE SEEN.
I C-CANNOT.
NO VULCAN COULD
EXPLAIN FURTHER.
I'M TRYING
TO HELP YOU, SPOCK.
ASK ME NO
FURTHER QUESTIONS.
I WILL NOT ANSWER.
I ORDER YOU TO REPORT
TO THE SICK BAY.
SICK BAY?
COMPLETE EXAMINATION.
McCOY'S WAITING.
OH, COME IN, SPOCK.
I'M ALL READY FOR YOU.
MY ORDERS WERE TO
REPORT TO SICK BAY,
DOCTOR.
I HAVE DONE SO.
AND NOW I'LL GO
TO MY QUARTERS.
MY ORDERS WERE TO GIVE YOU
A THOROUGH PHYSICAL.
IN CASE YOU HADN'T NOTICED,
I HAVE TO ANSWER TO
THE SAME COMMANDING
OFFICER THAT YOU DO.
COME ON, SPOCK.
YIELD TO THE LOGIC
OF THE SITUATION.
VERY WELL, DOCTOR.
EXAMINE ME...
FOR ALL THE GOOD
IT'LL DO EITHER OF US.
HOW DO YOU
FIGURE IT, CHEKOV?
FIRST WE'RE GOING
TO VULCAN,
THEN WE'RE
GOING TO ALTAIR,
THEN WE'RE HEADED
TO VULCAN AGAIN,
AND NOW WE'RE HEADED
BACK TO ALTAIR.
I THINK I'M GOING
TO GET SPACESICK.
JIM, YOU'VE GOT TO
GET SPOCK TO VULCAN.
BONES, I WILL, I WILL.
AS SOON AS THIS
MISSION IS--
NO. NOW, RIGHT AWAY.
IF YOU DON'T
GET HIM TO VULCAN
WITHIN A WEEK,
8 DAYS AT THE
OUTSIDE, HE'LL DIE.
HE'LL DIE, JIM.
WHY...
MUST HE DIE?
WHY WITHIN EIGHT DAYS?
EXPLAIN.
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU...KEEP SAYING THAT.
ARE YOU A DOCTOR,
OR AREN'T YOU?
THERE'S A GROWING
IMBALANCE OF
BODY FUNCTIONS...
AS IF IN OUR BODIES
HUGE AMOUNTS
OF ADRENALIN
WERE CONSTANTLY
BEING PUMPED INTO
OUR BLOODSTREAMS.
NOW I CAN'T TRACE IT
DOWN IN MY BIOCOMPS,
SPOCK WON'T TELL ME
WHAT IT IS,
BUT IF IT ISN'T
STOPPED SOMEHOW,
THE PHYSICAL AND
EMOTIONAL PRESSURES
WILL SIMPLY KILL HIM.
YOU SAY YOU'RE CONVINCED
HE KNOWS WHAT IT IS?
HE DOES...
AS HE'S AS
TIGHT-LIPPED
ABOUT IT
AS AN ALDEBERON
SHELLMOUTH.
NO USE TO
ASK HIM, JIM.
HE WON'T TALK.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
COME.
STAY.
McCOY HAS GIVEN ME
HIS MEDICAL EVALUATION
OF YOUR CONDITION.
HE SAYS YOU'RE
GOING TO DIE UNLESS
SOMETHING IS DONE.
WHAT?
IS IT SOMETHING
ONLY YOUR PLANET
CAN DO FOR YOU?
SPOCK!
YOU'VE BEEN CALLED
THE BEST FIRST OFFICER
IN THE FLEET.
THAT'S AN ENORMOUS
ASSET TO ME.
IF I HAVE TO LOSE
THAT FIRST OFFICER,
I WANT TO KNOW WHY.
IT IS A THING NO
OUTWORLDER MAY KNOW...
EXCEPT THOSE VERY FEW
WHO HAVE BEEN INVOLVED.
A VULCAN UNDERSTANDS,
BUT EVEN WE
DO NOT SPEAK OF IT
AMONG OURSELVES.
IT IS A DEEPLY
PERSONAL THING.
CAN YOU SEE THAT,
CAPTAIN,
AND UNDERSTAND?
NO, I DO NOT
UNDERSTAND.
EXPLAIN.
CONSIDER THAT
AN ORDER.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE SOME
THINGS WHICH TRANSCEND
EVEN THE DISCIPLINE
OF THE SERVICE.
WOULD IT HELP
IF I TOLD YOU
THAT I'LL TREAT
THIS AS TOTALLY
CONFIDENTIAL?
IT HAS TO DO WITH...
BIOLOGY.
WHAT?
WHAT KIND
OF BIOLOGY?
VULCAN BIOLOGY.
YOU MEAN
THE BIOLOGY
OF VULCANS?
BIOLOGY AS IN...
REPRODUCTION?
WELL, UH...
THERE'S NO NEED
TO BE EMBARRASSED
ABOUT IT, MR. SPOCK.
IT HAPPENS
TO THE BIRDS
AND THE BEES.
THE BIRDS AND THE BEES
ARE NOT VULCANS, CAPTAIN.
IF THEY WERE...
IF ANY CREATURE
AS PROUDLY LOGICAL AS US
WERE TO HAVE THEIR LOGIC
RIPPED FROM THEM
AS THIS TIME DOES TO US...
HOW DO VULCANS
CHOOSE THEIR MATES?
HAVEN'T YOU WONDERED?
I GUESS THE REST
OF US ASSUME
THAT IT'S DONE...
QUITE LOGICALLY.
NO.
IT IS NOT.
WE SHIELD IT
WITH A RITUAL...
AND CUSTOMS SHROUDED
IN ANTIQUITY.
YOU HUMANS
HAVE NO CONCEPTION.
IT STRIPS OUR MINDS
FROM US.
IT BRINGS A MADNESS
WHICH RIPS AWAY
OUR VENEER
OF CIVILIZATION.
IT IS THE
POHN FAHRR...
THE TIME OF MATING.
THERE ARE PRECEDENTS
IN NATURE, CAPTAIN--
THE GIANT EEL BIRDS
OF REGULUS 5.
ONCE EACH 11 YEARS
THEY MUST RETURN
TO THE CAVERNS
WHERE THEY HATCHED.
ON YOUR EARTH,
THE SALMON...
THEY MUST RETURN
TO THAT ONE STREAM
WHERE THEY WERE BORN
TO SPAWN...
OR DIE IN TRYING.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
A FISH, MR. SPOCK.
YOU'RE--
NO. NOR AM I MAN.
I'M A VULCAN.
I'D HOPED I WOULD
BE SPARED THIS,
BUT THE ANCIENT DRIVES
ARE TOO STRONG.
EVENTUALLY,
THEY CATCH UP WITH US,
AND WE ARE DRIVEN BY
FORCES WE CANNOT CONTROL
TO RETURN HOME
AND TAKE A WIFE...
OR DIE.
I HAVEN'T HEARD
A WORD YOU'VE SAID,
AND...
I'LL GET YOU
TO VULCAN SOMEHOW.
Kirk: LIEUTENANT, GET ME
ADMIRAL KOMACK
AT STARFLEET COMMAND,
SECTOR NINE.
PIPE IT DOWN
TO McCOY'S OFFICE.
STARFLEET COMMAND.
YES, SIR.
MR. SULU,
YOU DON'T THINK...
MAYBE YOU OUGHT
TO PLOT A COURSE
BACK FOR VULCAN,
JUST IN CASE.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Uhura: COMMUNICATION
TO MR. SPOCK.
LIEUTENANT UHURA HERE.
CAPTAIN ASKED ME TO--
LET ME ALONE...
LET ME ALONE!
CAPTAIN, YOU'RE MAKING
A MOST UNUSUAL REQUEST.
I'M AWARE
OF THAT, SIR,
BUT IT'S OF
THE UTMOST
IMPORTANCE.
YOU MUST GIVE ME
PERMISSION TO DIVERT
TO VULCAN.
BUT YOU REFUSE TO EXPLAIN
WHY IT IS SO IMPORTANT.
I CAN'T, SIR,
BUT BELIEVE ME,
I WOULDN'T MAKE
SUCH A REQUEST--
ALTAIR 6
IS NO ORDINARY MATTER.
THAT AREA IS JUST
PUTTING ITSELF TOGETHER
AFTER A LONG
INTERPLANETARY CONFLICT.
THIS INAUGURATION WILL STABILIZE
THE ENTIRE ALTAIR SYSTEM.
OUR APPEARANCE THERE
IS A DEMONSTRATION OF
FRIENDSHIP AND STRENGTH
WHICH WILL CAUSE RIPPLES
CLEAR TO THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
SIR...
THE DELAY WOULD BE,
AT MOST, A DAY.
I CAN HARDLY
BELIEVE THAT--
YOU'LL PROCEED TO ALTAIR 6
AS ORDERED.
SUBJECT IS CLOSED.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
STARFLEET OUT.
WELL...THAT'S THAT.
NO, IT'S NOT.
I KNOW THE ALTAIR
SITUATION.
WE WOULD BE ONE
OF THREE STARSHIPS--
VERY IMPRESSIVE,
VERY DIPLOMATIC--
BUT IT'S SIMPLY
NOT THAT VITAL.
YOU CAN'T GO OFF TO VULCAN
AGAINST STARFLEET ORDERS.
YOU'LL BE BUSTED--
I CAN'T LET SPOCK DIE,
CAN I, BONES?
AND HE WILL
IF WE GO TO ALTAIR.
I OWE HIM MY LIFE
A DOZEN TIMES OVER.
ISN'T THAT WORTH A CAREER?
HE'S MY FRIEND.
BRIDGE, NAVIGATION.
MR. CHEKOV...
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR VULCAN.
TELL ENGINEERING
I WANT WARP 8 OR BETTER.
PUSH HER
FOR ALL SHE'LL TAKE.
COURSE ALREADY PLOTTED.
LAYING IT IN, SIR.
I SEE.
VERY WELL.
CARRY ON, MR. CHEKOV.
KIRK OUT.
MISS CHAPEL.
YES, MR. SPOCK?
I HAD A MOST
STARTLING DREAM.
YOU WERE TRYING TO
TELL ME SOMETHING,
BUT I COULDN'T
HEAR YOU.
IT WOULD BE
ILLOGICAL FOR US
TO PROTEST AGAINST
OUR NATURES.
DON'T YOU THINK?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOUR FACE IS WET.
I CAME TO TELL YOU THAT
WE ARE BOUND FOR VULCAN.
WE'LL BE THERE
IN JUST A FEW DAYS.
VULCAN.
MISS CHAPEL.
MY NAME IS CHRISTINE.
YES, I KNOW,
CHRISTINE.
WOULD YOU MAKE
ME SOME OF THAT
PLOMIK SOUP?
OH, I'D BE VERY GLAD
TO DO THAT, MR. SPOCK.
BRIDGE.
IT IS OBVIOUS THAT
YOU HAVE SURMISED
MY PROBLEM, DOCTOR.
MY COMPLIMENTS
ON YOUR INSIGHT.
CAPTAIN, THERE IS
A THING THAT HAPPENS
TO VULCANS AT THIS TIME.
ALMOST AN INSANITY,
WHICH YOU WOULD NO DOUBT
FIND DISTASTEFUL.
WILL I?
YOU'VE BEEN MOST
PATIENT WITH MY
KINDS OF MADNESS.
THEN WOULD YOU BEAM DOWN
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE
AND STAND WITH ME?
THERE IS
A BRIEF CEREMONY.
IS IT PERMITTED?
IT IS MY RIGHT.
BY TRADITION,
THE MALE IS ACCOMPANIED
BY HIS CLOSEST FRIENDS.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
I ALSO REQUEST McCOY
TO ACCOMPANY ME.
I SHALL BE
HONORED, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE STANDING BY
ON VULCAN HAILING
FREQUENCIES, SIR.
OPEN THE CHANNEL,
LIEUTENANT.
VULCAN SPACE CENTRAL,
THIS IS THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
REQUESTING PERMISSION
TO ASSUME STANDARD ORBIT.
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
FROM VULCAN
SPACE CENTRAL--
PERMISSION GRANTED,
AND FROM ALL OF
VULCAN, WELCOME.
IS COMMANDER SPOCK
WITH YOU?
THIS IS SPOCK.
STAND BY TO ACTIVATE
YOUR CENTRAL VIEWER,
PLEASE.
DOCTOR,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
SPOCK...
IT IS I.
T'PRING...
PARTED FROM ME
AND NEVER PARTED.
NEVER AND ALWAYS
TOUCHING AND TOUCHED.
WE MEET AT
THE APPOINTED PLACE.
SPOCK...
PARTED FROM ME
AND NEVER PARTED,
NEVER AND ALWAYS
TOUCHING AND TOUCHED.
I AWAIT YOU.
SHE'S LOVELY, MR. SPOCK.
WHO IS SHE?
SHE IS T'PRING...
MY WIFE.
THIS IS THE LAND
OF MY FAMILY.
IT HAS BEEN HELD BY US
FOR MORE THAN 2,000 EARTH YEARS.
THIS IS OUR PLACE
OF KOONUT KALIFFEE.
HE CALLED IT
KOONUT WHAT?
HE DESCRIBED IT
TO ME AS MEANING
"MARRIAGE
OR CHALLENGE."
IN THE DISTANT PAST,
VULCANS KILLED
TO WIN THEIR MATES.
THEY STILL GO MAD
AT THIS TIME.
PERHAPS IT'S
THE PRICE THEY PAY
FOR HAVING NO EMOTIONS
THE REST OF THE TIME.
LOVELY. I WISH
THE BREEZE
WERE COOLER.
YEAH.
"HOT AS VULCAN."
NOW I UNDERSTAND
WHAT THAT PHRASE MEANS.
THE ATMOSPHERE'S
THINNER THAN EARTH.
[GONG]
I WONDER WHEN HIS
T'PRING ARRIVES.
THE MARRIAGE PARTY
APPROACHES.
I HEAR THEM.
MARRIAGE PARTY?
YOU SAID T'PRING
WAS YOUR WIFE.
BY OUR PARENTS'
ARRANGEMENT...
A CEREMONY...
WHILE WE WERE BUT
7 YEARS OF AGE...
LESS
THAN A MARRIAGE...
BUT MORE
THAN A BETROTHAL.
ONE TOUCHES
THE OTHER
IN ORDER TO FEEL
EACH OTHER'S
THOUGHTS.
IN THIS WAY,
OUR MINDS WERE
LOCKED TOGETHER...
SO THAT,
AT THE PROPER TIME,
WE WOULD
BOTH BE DRAWN
TO...
KOONUT KALIFFEE.
[BELLS RINGING]
BONES...YOU KNOW
WHO THAT IS?
T'PAU...
THE ONLY PERSON
TO EVER TURN
DOWN A SEAT
ON THE FEDERATION
COUNCIL.
T'PAU? OFFICIATING
AT SPOCK'S WEDDING?
HE NEVER MENTIONED
THAT HIS FAMILY
WAS THIS IMPORTANT.
SPOCK...
ARE OUR CEREMONIES
FOR OUTWORLDERS?
THEY ARE
NOT OUTWORLDERS.
THEY ARE MY FRIENDS.
I AM PERMITTED THIS.
THIS IS KIRK.
MA'AM.
AND THEE ARE CALLED?
LEONARD McCOY, MA'AM.
THEE NAMES
THESE OUTWORLDERS
FRIENDS.
HOW DOES THEE PLEDGE
THEIR BEHAVIOR?
WITH MY LIFE, T'PAU.
WHAT THEY ARE
ABOUT TO SEE...
COMES DOWN
FROM THE TIME
OF THE BEGINNING...
WITHOUT CHANGE.
THIS IS
THE VULCAN HEART.
THE VULCAN SOUL.
THIS IS OUR WAY.
KALIFFARR.
KALIFFEE!
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT HAPPENED?
SHE CHOOSES
THE CHALLENGE.
WITH HIM?
HE ACTS ONLY
IF COWARDICE
IS SEEN.
SHE WILL CHOOSE
HER CHAMPION.
SPOCK...
DO NOT ATTEMPT
TO SPEAK AT HIM,
KIRK.
HE IS DEEP
IN THE PLAKTAU...
THE BLOOD FEVER.
HE WILL NOT SPEAK
WITH THEE AGAIN...
UNTIL HE HAS
PASSED THROUGH
WHAT IS TO COME.
IF THEE WISHES
TO DEPART...
THEE MAY LEAVE NOW.
WE'LL STAY.
SPOCK CHOSE
HIS FRIENDS WELL.
MA'AM, I DON'T
UNDERSTAND. ARE YOU
TRYING TO SAY
THAT SHE
REJECTED HIM,
THAT SHE DOESN'T
WANT HIM?
HE WILL HAVE TO
FIGHT FOR HER.
IT IS HER RIGHT.
T'PRING, THEE HAS CHOSEN
THE KALIFFEE,
THE CHALLENGE.
THEE ARE PREPARED
TO BECOME THE PROPERTY
OF THE VICTOR?
I AM PREPARED.
SPOCK, DOES THEE
ACCEPT CHALLENGE,
ACCORDING TO OUR LAWS
AND CUSTOMS?
DO YOU THINK SPOCK
CAN TAKE HIM?
I DOUBT IT...
NOT IN HIS PRESENT
CONDITION.
T'PRING, THEE WILL
CHOOSE THY CHAMPION.
AS IT WAS IN THE DAWN
OF OUR DAYS,
AS IT IS TODAY,
AS IT WILL BE
FOR ALL TOMORROWS,
I MAKE MY CHOICE.
THIS ONE.
NO! I AM
TO BE THE ONE.
IT WAS AGREED.
BE SILENT!
HEAR ME.
I HAVE MADE
THE ANCIENT CLAIM.
I CLAIM THE RIGHT.
THE WOMAN IS--
KROYKAH!
I ASK FORGIVENESS.
KIRK...
T'PRING IS WITHIN
HER RIGHTS,
BUT OUR LAWS AND CUSTOMS
ARE NOT BINDING ON THEE.
THEE ARE FREE
TO DECLINE...
WITH NO HARM
ON THYSELF.
T'PAU...
THEE SPEAKS?
MY FRIEND...
DOES NOT UNDERSTAND.
THE CHOICE
HAS BEEN MADE, SPOCK.
IT IS UP TO HIM NOW.
HE DOES NOT...KNOW.
I WILL DO...
WHAT I MUST...
T'PAU...
BUT NOT WITH HIM!
HIS BLOOD...
DOES NOT BURN.
HE IS MY FRIEND!
IT IS SAID...
THY VULCAN BLOOD IS THIN.
ARE THEE VULCAN...
OR ARE THEE HUMAN?
I BURN...T'PAU.
MY EYES...ARE FLAME.
MY HEART...IS FLAME.
THEE HAS THE POWER,
T'PAU.
IN THE NAME...
OF MY FATHERS,
FORBID. FORBID!
T'PAU...
I PLEAD...WITH THEE!
I BEG!
THEE HAS PRIDED THYSELF
ON THY VULCAN HERITAGE.
IT IS DECIDED.
WHAT HAPPENS TO SPOCK
IF I DECLINE?
ANOTHER CHAMPION
WILL BE SELECTED.
DO NOT INTERFERE, KIRK.
KEEP THY PLACE.
YOU CAN'T DO IT,
JIM.
I CAN'T?
NO. SHE SAID THEIR
LAWS AND CUSTOMS
WERE NOT BINDING
ON YOU.
AND YOU SAID SPOCK
MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO HANDLE HIM.
IF I CAN
KNOCK SPOCK OUT WITHOUT
REALLY HURTING HIM...
IN THIS CLIMATE?
IF THE HEAT
DOESN'T GET YOU,
THE THIN AIR WILL.
YOU CAN'T DO IT!
IF I GET
INTO ANY TROUBLE,
I'LL QUIT,
AND SPOCK WINS,
AND HONOR IS SATISFIED.
JIM, LISTEN,
IF YOU--
BONES...
HE'S MY FIRST OFFICER,
MY FRIEND.
I DISREGARDED
STARFLEET ORDERS
TO BRING HIM HERE.
ANOTHER THING,
THAT'S...T'PAU...
A VULCAN...
ALL OF VULCAN
IN ONE PACKAGE.
HOW CAN I BACK OUT
IN FRONT OF HER?
IT IS DONE.
KIRK...DECIDE.
I ACCEPT...
THE CHALLENGE.
HERE BEGINS
THE ACT OF COMBAT
FOR POSSESSION
OF THE WOMAN T'PRING.
AS IT WAS AT THE TIME
OF THE BEGINNING,
SO IT IS NOW.
BRING FORTH THE LIRPA.
IF BOTH SURVIVE
THE LIRPA...
COMBAT WILL CONTINUE
WITH THE AHN WOON.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN...
"IF BOTH SURVIVE"?
THIS COMBAT IS
TO THE DEATH.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE...
MA'AM.
WHO SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT A FIGHT
TO THE DEATH?
THESE MEN ARE FRIENDS.
TO FORCE THEM TO FIGHT
TILL ONE OF THEM IS KILLED--
I CAN FORGIVE
SUCH A DISPLAY ONLY ONCE.
CHALLENGE WAS GIVEN...
AND LAWFULLY ACCEPTED.
IT HAS BEGUN.
LET NO ONE INTERFERE.
SPOCK! NO!
KROYKAH!
IS THIS VULCAN CHIVALRY?
THE AIR'S TOO HOT
AND THIN FOR KIRK.
HE'S NOT USED TO IT.
THE AIR IS THE AIR.
WHAT CAN BE DONE?
I CAN COMPENSATE
FOR THE ATMOSPHERE
AND THE TEMPERATURE
WITH THIS.
AT LEAST
IT WILL GIVE KIRK
A FIGHTING CHANCE.
THEE MAY PROCEED.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO KILL HIM, JIM.
KILL SPOCK?
THAT'S NOT WHAT WE CAME
TO VULCAN FOR, IS IT?
WHAT'S THAT?
IT'S A TRIOX COMPOUND.
IT'LL HELP YOU BREATHE.
NOW BE CAREFUL!
SOUND MEDICAL ADVICE.
THE AHN WOON.
KROYKAH!
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF OF HIM, SPOCK!
IT'S FINISHED.
HE'S DEAD.
I GRIEVE WITH THEE.
McCOY TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE,
LIEUTENANT UHURA HERE.
HAVE
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
STAND BY TO BEAM UP
THE LANDING PARTY.
AS STRANGE AS IT
MAY SEEM, MR. SPOCK,
YOU'RE IN COMMAND NOW.
ANY ORDERS?
YES.
I'LL FOLLOW YOU UP
IN A FEW MINUTES.
YOU WILL INSTRUCT
MR. CHEKOV
TO PLOT A COURSE...
FOR THE NEAREST
STARBASE...
WHERE I MUST
SURRENDER MYSELF
TO THE AUTHORITIES.
T'PRING...
EXPLAIN.
SPECIFY.
WHY THE CHALLENGE?
AND WHY YOU
CHOSE MY CAPTAIN
AS YOUR CHAMPION?
STONN WANTED ME.
I WANTED HIM.
I SEE NO LOGIC
IN PREFERRING STONN
OVER ME.
YOU HAVE BECOME
MUCH KNOWN
AMONG OUR PEOPLE,
SPOCK,
ALMOST A LEGEND.
AND AS THE YEARS
WENT BY,
I CAME TO KNOW
THAT I DID NOT WANT
TO BE THE CONSORT
OF A LEGEND...
BUT BY THE LAWS
OF OUR PEOPLE,
I COULD
ONLY DIVORCE YOU
BY THE KAHLIFFEE.
THERE WAS ALSO STONN
WHO WANTED VERY MUCH
TO BE MY CONSORT,
AND I WANTED HIM.
IF YOUR CAPTAIN
WERE VICTOR,
HE WOULD NOT WANT ME,
SO I WOULD HAVE STONN.
IF YOU WERE VICTOR,
YOU WOULD FREE ME
BECAUSE I HAD DARED
TO CHALLENGE
AND AGAIN
I WOULD HAVE STONN.
BUT IF YOU
DID NOT FREE ME,
IT WOULD BE THE SAME.
FOR YOU WOULD BE GONE,
AND I WOULD
HAVE YOUR NAME
AND YOUR PROPERTY,
AND STONN WOULD
STILL BE THERE.
LOGICAL...
FLAWLESSLY LOGICAL.
I AM HONORED.
STONN...
SHE IS YOURS.
AFTER A TIME...
YOU MAY FIND
THAT HAVING...
IS NOT SO PLEASING
A THING AFTER ALL
AS WANTING.
IT IS NOT LOGICAL,
BUT IT IS OFTEN TRUE.
SPOCK HERE.
STAND BY TO BEAM UP.
LIVE LONG, T'PAU,
AND PROSPER.
LIVE LONG
AND PROSPER, SPOCK.
I SHALL DO NEITHER.
I HAVE KILLED
MY CAPTAIN...
AND MY FRIEND.
ENERGIZE.
DOCTOR, I SHALL BE
RESIGNING MY COMMISSION
IMMEDIATELY, OF COURSE.
UH, SPOCK--
SO I WOULD APPRECIATE
YOUR MAKING
THE FINAL ARRANGEMENTS.
SPOCK, I--
DOCTOR, PLEASE,
LET ME FINISH.
THERE CAN BE NO EXCUSE
FOR THE CRIME
OF WHICH I'M GUILTY.
I INTEND TO OFFER
NO DEFENSE.
FURTHERMORE, I SHALL ORDER
MR. SCOTT TO TAKE IMMEDIATE
COMMAND OF THIS VESSEL.
DON'T YOU THINK YOU
BETTER CHECK
WITH ME FIRST?
CAPTAIN!
JIM!
I'M...PLEASED...
TO SEE YOU, CAPTAIN.
YOU SEEM...
UNINJURED.
I AM AT SOMETHING
OF A LOSS
TO UNDERSTAND IT,
HOWEVER.
BLAME McCOY.
THAT WAS NO TRIOX COMPOUND
HE SHOT ME WITH.
HE SLIPPED IN
A NEUROPARALYZER.
KNOCKED ME OUT,
SIMULATED DEATH.
INDEED.
NURSE, WOULD YOU MIND,
PLEASE?
SPOCK, WHAT HAPPENED
DOWN THERE? THE GIRL?
THE WEDDING?
AH, YES, THE GIRL.
HMM,
MOST INTERESTING.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
THE COMBAT.
WHEN I THOUGHT I HAD
KILLED THE CAPTAIN,
I FOUND I'D LOST ALL
INTEREST IN T'PRING.
THE MADNESS WAS GONE.
[BOSUN'S WHISTLE]
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN KIRK, MESSAGE
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND,
TOP PRIORITY.
RELAY IT, LIEUTENANT.
RESPONSE
TO T'PAU'S REQUEST
FOR DIVERSION
OF ENTERPRISE
TO PLANET VULCAN
HEREBY APPROVED.
ANY REASONABLE
DELAY GRANTED.
KOMACK, ADMIRAL,
STARFLEET COMMAND.
WELL, A LITTLE LATE,
BUT I'M GLAD THEY'RE
SEEING IT OUR WAY.
HOW ABOUT THAT T'PAU?
THEY COULDN'T
TURN HER DOWN.
MR. CHEKOV,
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR ALTAIR 6.
LEAVE ORBIT WHEN
READY. KIRK OUT.
THERE'S JUST
ONE THING, MR. SPOCK.
YOU CAN'T TELL ME
THAT WHEN YOU FIRST
SAW JIM ALIVE
THAT YOU WEREN'T
ON THE VERGE OF GIVING US
AN EMOTIONAL SCENE
THAT WOULD HAVE
BROUGHT THE HOUSE DOWN.
MERELY MY QUITE LOGICAL
RELIEF THAT STARFLEET
HAD NOT LOST A HIGHLY
PROFICIENT CAPTAIN.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
I UNDERSTAND.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE, MR. SPOCK,
YOUR REACTION WAS
QUITE LOGICAL.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
IN A PIG'S EYE!
COME ON, SPOCK.
LET'S GO MIND
THE STORE.