HERE'S THE REPORT
ON POLEX 5, CAPTAIN.
THIS ENTIRE SYSTEM HAS
BEEN ALMOST THE SAME.
THERE'S A STRANGE LACK
OF INTELLIGENT LIFE
ON THE PLANET.
IT BUGS
THE PERCENTAGES.
BUGS THE--
WELL, CARRY OUT
THE STANDARD PROCEDURES
ON POLEX 4.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT,
YOU LOOK A BIT TIRED
THIS MORNING.
WELL, I WAS UP ALL NIGHT
WORKING ON THIS REPORT, SIR.
WELL, IN THAT CASE,
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
A WEE BIT OF COFFEE
TO GET YOU
BACK IN SHAPE.
JOIN ME, CAROLYN?
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
JUST LET ME GIVE THIS
TO MR. SPOCK.
BONES...
COULD YOU GET THAT EXCITED
OVER A CUP OF COFFEE?
WELL, EVEN FROM HERE I CAN
TELL HIS PULSE RATE'S UP.
GENTLEMEN.
COME ALONG, MY DEAR.
I'M NOT SURE
I LIKE THAT, JIM.
WHY, BONES?
SCOTTY'S A GOOD MAN.
AND HE THINKS HE'S
THE RIGHT MAN FOR HER,
BUT I'M NOT SURE
SHE THINKS
HE'S THE RIGHT MAN.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
SHE'S A WOMAN--
ALL WOMAN.
MM-HMM.
ONE DAY SHE'LL
FIND THE RIGHT MAN.
OFF SHE'LL GO,
OUT OF THE SERVICE.
MM-HMM.
I LIKE TO
THINK OF IT
NOT SO MUCH AS
LOSING AN OFFICER
AS GAINING--
COME ALONG.
ACTUALLY, I'M
LOSING AN OFFICER.
ENTERING STANDARD ORBIT
AROUND POLEX 4, SIR.
CARTOGRAPHIC DETAIL,
STAND BY.
STANDING BY, SIR.
PRELIMINARY REPORTS,
MR. SPOCK.
POLEX 4--
CLASS "M" TYPE PLANET,
OXYGEN AND NITROGEN
ATMOSPHERE.
SENSORS INDICATE
NO LIFE FORMS.
APPROXIMATE AGE--
4 BILLION YEARS.
JUDGE NO REASON
FOR CONTACT.
IN ALL RESPECTS,
QUITE ORDINARY, CAPTAIN.
CARTOGRAPHIC SECTIONS,
IMPLEMENT STANDARD ORDERS.
Uhura: ALL CARTOGRAPHIC
STANDARDS--FULL AUTOMATIC.
CAPTAIN?
WHAT IN THE NAME OF...
ANALYSIS, MR. SPOCK.
MOMENTARILY.
AM I...
SEEING THINGS?
NOT UNLESS I AM,
TOO.
CAPTAIN,
THAT THING'S
A GIANT HAND.
WHAT IS IT, MR. SPOCK?
IS IT A...
A HAND?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
NOT LIVING TISSUE.
A TRICK, THEN?
A PROJECTION?
NOT A PROJECTION,
SIR.
A FIELD OF ENERGY.
HARD ABOUT.
WE CAN'T SEEM
TO GET AWAY FROM IT.
IT'S ALMOST
AS IF IT MEANS
TO GRAB US.
REVERSE ALL ENGINES.
ALL ENGINES
REVERSED.
WE'RE DEAD STILL,
CAPTAIN.
HELM DOESN'T ANSWER.
WE CAN'T MOVE.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE,"
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3468.1.
WHILE APPROACHING
POLEX 4,
A PLANET IN THE BETA
GEMINORUM SYSTEM,
THE "ENTERPRISE"
HAS BEEN STOPPED IN SPACE
BY AN UNKNOWN FORCE
OF SOME KIND.
LIEUTENANT,
RELAY OUR POSITION
AND CIRCUMSTANCES
TO STARBASE 12
IMMEDIATELY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MR. SULU...
TRY ROCKING THE SHIP.
FULL IMPULSE POWER
FORWARD AND BACK.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
DAMAGE REPORT
COMING IN, CAPTAIN.
SITUATION
UNDER CONTROL.
MINOR DAMAGE--
STATIONS 3, 7, AND 19.
SICK BAY REPORTS
5 MINOR INJURIES
ALL BEING TREATED.
THANK YOU.
MR. SULU?
APPLYING THRUST,
SIR.
NO RESULTS, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE STUCK TIGHT.
MR. SPOCK...
STATUS.
THE SHIP IS ALMOST
COMPLETELY ENCIRCLED
BY THE FIELD.
IT RESEMBLES
A CONVENTIONAL
FORCE FIELD
BUT ON UNUSUAL
WAVELENGTHS.
DESPITE ITS APPEARANCE--
THAT OF A HUMAN
APPENDAGE--
IT IS DEFINITELY NOT
LIVING TISSUE.
IT IS ENERGY.
THANK YOU.
MR. SULU...
OUR FORWARD TRACTOR BEAMS--
ADJUST TO REPEL.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
[BEEP]
STANDING BY.
ACTIVATE.
INEFFECTIVE,
CAPTAIN.
THERE DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE ANYTHING
TO PUSH AGAINST.
CAPTAIN, A MOST
CURIOUS DEVELOPMENT
ON SCANNER 57.
LET'S ALL TAKE A LOOK
AT IT, MR. SPOCK.
SCREEN ON,
CAPTAIN.
ACTIVITY ON
HAILING CHANNEL 3, SIR.
PUT IT ON AUDIO,
LIEUTENANT.
THE EONS HAVE PASSED,
AND WHAT HAS BEEN WRITTEN
HAS COME ABOUT.
YOU ARE MOST WELCOME,
MY BELOVED CHILDREN.
YOUR PLACES AWAIT YOU.
RESPONSE FREQUENCY,
LIEUTENANT.
CALCULATED.
CHANNEL OPEN, SIR.
YOU HAVE LEFT
YOUR PLAINS AND VALLEYS
AND MADE THIS BOLD VENTURE.
SO IT WAS IN THE BEGINNING.
YOU HAVE MADE ME PROUD.
NOW YOU CAN REST.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK,
COMMANDING THE U.S.S.
"ENTERPRISE."
PLEASE
IDENTIFY YOURSELF.
WE SHALL REMEMBER TOGETHER.
WE SHALL DRINK
THE SACRAMENTAL WINE.
THERE SHALL BE
THE MUSIC OF THE PIPES.
THE LONG WAIT
HAS ENDED.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR STOPPING THE SHIP?
YES.
I CAUSED THE WIND
TO WITHDRAW
FROM YOUR SAILS.
GIVE IT BACK,
THEN WE'LL TALK.
IT HAS BEEN 5,000 YEARS.
HAVE YOU LEARNED NO
PATIENCE IN THAT TIME?
I DON'T KNOW
WHO OR WHAT YOU ARE,
BUT I MUST WARN YOU,
WE HAVE THE POWER TO
DEFEND OURSELVES.
IF YOU VALUE YOUR SAFETY,
RELEASE THIS SHIP.
YOU HAVE THE SAME FIRE.
HOW LIKE YOUR FATHERS
YOU ARE--
AGAMEMNON, HECTOR,
ODYSSEUS.
NEVER MIND
THE HISTORY LESSON.
RELEASE THE SHIP!
YOU WILL OBEY ME,
LEST I CLOSE
MY HAND...THUS.
EXTERNAL PRESSURE
BUILDING UP, CAPTAIN.
800 GSC
AND CLIMBING.
COMPENSATE.
1,000 GSC
AND CLIMBING.
AAH!
IT'S BECOMING
CRITICAL, CAPTAIN.
WE CAN'T HANDLE IT.
ALL RIGHT! WHATEVER
YOU'RE DOING, TURN IT OFF!
YOU WIN!
PRESSURE IS GONE,
CAPTAIN.
SPACE
NORMAL ON HULL.
THAT WAS YOUR FIRST LESSON.
REMEMBER IT.
CAPTAIN KIRK, I INVITE
YOU AND YOUR OFFICERS
TO JOIN ME,
BUT DO NOT
BRING THAT ONE,
THE ONE WITH
THE POINTED EARS.
HE IS MUCH LIKE PAN,
AND PAN ALWAYS BORED ME.
NO SAD FACES.
THIS IS A TIME TO
REJOICE, NOT TO FEAR.
YOU ARE RETURNING HOME.
LET YOUR HEARTS
PREPARE TO SING.
LET'S GO, BONES.
YOU IN GOOD VOICE?
SURE IT'S WISE,
JIM?
IF WE DON'T
ACCEPT HIS INVITATION,
WE'LL HAVE
A CRUSHED EGGSHELL
WHERE THIS SHIP
USED TO BE.
VERBOSE, ISN'T HE?
INSULTED, SPOCK?
INSULTS ARE EFFECTIVE
ONLY WHERE EMOTION
IS PRESENT.
GOOD.
WE'LL TACKLE HIM
TOGETHER.
WE ALREADY
KNOW THE QUESTIONS.
YOU'RE THE BEST MAN
TO FIND THE ANSWERS.
TRICORDERS.
WHAT AM I DOING
DOWN HERE, DOCTOR?
WELL, YOU'RE
THE A &amp; A OFFICER,
AREN'T YOU?
ARCHAEOLOGY,
ANTHROPOLOGY,
ANCIENT
CIVILIZATIONS.
CORRECT.
WELL, WE'RE GOING
TO NEED HELP
IN ALL
THOSE AREAS.
COME ON.
MY CHILDREN,
LONG HAVE I WAITED
FOR THIS MOMENT.
THE MEMORIES YOU BRING
OF YOUR LUSH
AND BEAUTIFUL EARTH,
THE GREEN FIELDS
AND BLUE SKIES,
THE SIMPLE SHEPHERDS
AND THEIR FLOCKS.
YOU KNOW OF EARTH?
YOU'VE BEEN THERE?
ONCE, I STRETCHED
OUT MY HAND,
AND EARTH TREMBLED.
AND I BREATHED
UPON IT,
AND SPRING RETURNED.
YOU MENTIONED
AGAMEMNON, HECTOR,
ODYSSEUS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT THEM?
SEARCH YOUR MOST
DISTANT MEMORIES,
THOSE OF THE THOUSANDS
OF YEARS PAST,
AND I AM THERE.
YOUR FATHERS KNEW ME
AND YOUR FATHER'S FATHERS.
I AM APOLLO.
AND I AM THE TSAR
OF ALL THE RUSSIAS.
MR. CHEKOV.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
I NEVER MET
A GOD BEFORE.
AND YOU HAVEN'T YET.
READINGS, DOCTOR.
SIMPLE HUMANOID,
CAPTAIN.
EVIDENTLY
NOT SO SIMPLE.
EARTH...
MOTHER OF THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
OF WOMEN IN THE UNIVERSE.
THAT, AT LEAST,
HAS NOT CHANGED.
I AM PLEASED.
YES, MY CHILDREN.
ZEUS, ATHENA,
APHRODITE, ARTEMIS--
A GALLANT BAND
OF TRAVELERS.
WE KNEW YOUR EARTH WELL
5,000 OF YOUR YEARS AGO.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE HERE
AT YOUR INVITATION.
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING US
WHAT YOU WANT
WITHOUT ALL
THE OLYMPIAN GENERALITIES?
YOU WILL NOT
LEAVE THIS PLACE.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
YOUR TRANSPORTATION DEVICE
NO LONGER FUNCTIONS.
[STATIC]
"ENTERPRISE,"
COME IN.
I WILL NOT
PERMIT THAT DEVICE
TO WORK,
EITHER, CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT?
YOU WILL WORSHIP ME,
AS YOUR FATHERS DID
BEFORE YOU.
IF YOU WANT TO PLAY GOD
AND CALL YOURSELF APOLLO,
THAT'S YOUR BUSINESS,
BUT YOU'RE NO GOD
TO US, MISTER!
I SAID YOU WILL
WORSHIP ME.
AND YOU'VE GOT
A LOT TO LEARN!
AND SO HAVE YOU!
LET THE LESSON
BEGIN!
WELCOME TO OLYMPUS,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
MR. SPOCK, I CAN'T CONTACT
THE LANDING PARTY.
ALL FREQUENCIES
ARE JAMMED.
TRY TO BREAK THROUGH
IT, LIEUTENANT.
TRANSPORTER
AND COMMUNICATIONS?
INEFFICIENT.
MR. SULU, RIG ALL
TRANSMISSION CIRCUITS
FOR MAXIMUM
POWER GENERATION.
COMPUTE FOR REVERSAL
OF POLARITY OF
THE FIELD
AROUND THE SHIP.
WORKING, SIR.
LIEUTENANT KYLE, I WANT A
COMPLETE SENSOR SCAN
OF THE PLANET.
- AYE, SIR.
- LOCATE ALL LIFE FORMS.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON DOWN THERE.
TO COIN A PHRASE...
FASCINATING.
ANALYSIS.
LIEUTENANT PALAMIS, WHAT
DO YOU KNOW ABOUT APOLLO?
APOLLO--TWIN BROTHER
OF ARTEMIS,
SON OF THE GOD ZEUS
AND LETO, A MORTAL.
HE WAS THE GOD
OF LIGHT AND PURITY.
HE WAS SKILLED
IN THE BOW AND
THE LYRE.
AND...THIS THING?
OBVIOUSLY, HE HAS SOME
KNOWLEDGE OF EARTH--
HIS CLASSICAL REFERENCES
AND THE APPEARANCE
OF ALL THIS.
I THINK THE
APPEARANCE OF ALL THIS
IS FOR OUR BENEFIT.
BONES?
WELL, I CAN'T
SAY MUCH
TILL I CHECK OUT
THESE READINGS.
HE LOOKS HUMAN,
BUT, OF COURSE, THAT
DOESN'T MEAN
A THING.
WHATEVER HE IS, SIR,
HE SEEMS TO CONTROL A
REMARKABLE TECHNOLOGY.
POWER IS
WHAT HE CONTROLS.
YOU CAN'T DO TRICKS
LIKE THAT WITHOUT ENERGY.
FINE, BUT
WHAT POWER
AND WHERE IS IT?
SCOUT AROUND WITH
YOUR TRICORDERS.
FIND THE SOURCE
OF THAT POWER.
BONES.
YES?
BONES, I WONDER
IF 5,000 YEARS AGO...
YOU HAVE A THEORY?
I HAVE AN IDEA.
WHAT IF HE...IS...
REALLY APOLLO?
WHAT?
CAPTAIN.
I WANT FROM YOU THAT
WHICH IS RIGHTFULLY MINE--
YOUR LOYALTY, YOUR TRIBUTE,
AND YOUR WORSHIP.
MAY I
ASK WHAT YOU OFFER
IN EXCHANGE
FOR THIS WORSHIP?
LIFE IN PARADISE.
AS SIMPLE
AND AS PLEASUREFUL
AS IT WAS THOSE
THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO
ON THAT BEAUTIFUL PLANET
SO FAR AWAY.
APOLLO...
WE'RE WILLING TO TALK,
BUT YOU'LL FIND
WE DON'T BOW
TO EVERY CREATURE
WHO HAPPENS TO HAVE
A BAG OF TRICKS.
AGAMEMNON WAS ONE
SUCH AS YOU,
AND HERCULES.
PRIDE AND ARROGANCE.
THEY DEFIED ME
UNTIL THEY FELT MY WRATH.
I WOULD LIKE
TO POINT OUT
THAT WE ARE QUITE CAPABLE
OF SOME WRATH OURSELVES.
I HAVE 430 PEOPLE
ON THAT SHIP
UP THERE.
NO, YOU DO NOT, CAPTAIN.
THEY ARE MINE--
TO SAVE, TO CHERISH,
OR TO DESTROY AT MY WILL.
BUT WHY?
WHAT YOU'VE
SAID SO FAR
MAKES NO
SENSE AT ALL.
HOW LIKE APHRODITE
AND ATHENA--
THE BEAUTY, GRACE--
AND YOU SEEM WISE
FOR A WOMAN.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
LIEUTENANT PALAMIS.
I MEAN YOUR NAME.
CAROLYN.
YES.
YOU ARE BEAUTIFUL.
YOU WOULD DO
APHRODITE CREDIT.
I WILL TELL YOU
A THOUSAND TALES,
STORIES OF
COURAGE AND LOVE.
YOU WILL KNOW WHAT IT
IS TO BE A GODDESS.
LEAVE HER ALONE.
YOU PROTEST?
YOU RISK MUCH.
AND SO DO YOU.
SCOTTY...
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
HOW'D YOU DO IT?
I'VE GROWN WEARY
OF DISCUSSION AND ARGUMENT.
CAPTAIN,
THE PHASERS.
ALL THE WORKING
PARTS ARE FUSED.
NONE OF YOUR TOYS
WILL FUNCTION.
YES.
YOU ARE A BEAUTY,
BUT LIKE ARTEMIS,
THE BOW ARM
SHOULD BE BARE.
OH.
OH, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
YES.
COME.
SHE'S NOT GOING
WITH YOU.
[THUNDER]
HE SHALL LEARN
THE DISCIPLINE
OF THE TEMPLE.
SO SHALL YOU ALL.
COME.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
I'LL GO.
WITHOUT FEAR.
SHE IS FIT, INDEED.
BONES, HOW IS HE?
STUNNED
BUT COMING AROUND.
I'M NOT SURE IT'S
WISE TO LET HER
GO OFF LIKE THAT.
HE WOULD HAVE BEEN
RATHER DIFFICULT
TO STOP.
YOU SAW HOW
CAPRICIOUS HE IS--
BENEVOLENT ONE MINUTE,
ANGRY THE NEXT.
ONE WRONG MOVE FROM
HER AND HE COULD
KILL HER.
MR. CHEKOV, I THINK
YOU BETTER CONTINUE
YOUR INVESTIGATION.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
HOW DO YOU FEEL,
SCOTTY?
OH, I'M TINGLING
ALL OVER.
DID HE TAKE HER WITH HIM?
IT SEEMS SO.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE GOT
TO STOP HIM.
HE WANTS HER.
THE WAY HE LOOKS AT HER--
MR. SCOTT,
I UNDERSTAND YOUR
CONCERN OVER HER,
BUT SHE VOLUNTEERED
TO GO WITH HIM,
HOPEFULLY
TO FIND OUT
MORE ABOUT HIM.
SHE'S DOING HER JOB.
I THINK IT'S ABOUT
TIME YOU STARTED
DOING YOURS.
WE'VE GOT TO
FIND OUT THE SOURCE
OF HIS POWER.
YOU'VE
GOT A TRICORDER.
USE IT IF
YOU'RE ABLE TO.
I'M ABLE, SIR.
AND ONE MORE THING--
I WANT NO MORE
UNAUTHORIZED ACTION
AGAINST APOLLO
OR WHATEVER HE IS.
THAT'S AN ORDER!
AYE, AYE, SIR.
BESIDES, YOU STIFF-NECKED
THISTLE HEAD,
YOU COULD HAVE
GOTTEN YOURSELF KILLED.
AYE.
SCOTTY DOESN'T
BELIEVE IN GODS.
APOLLO'S NO GOD...
BUT...
HE COULD HAVE BEEN
TAKEN FOR ONE, THOUGH,
ONCE.
SAY, 5,000 YEARS AGO,
A HIGHLY SOPHISTICATED
GROUP OF SPACE TRAVELERS
LANDED ON EARTH AROUND
THE MEDITERRANEAN.
YES.
TO THE SIMPLE SHEPHERDS
AND TRIBESMEN
OF EARLY GREECE,
CREATURES LIKE THAT
WOULD HAVE BEEN GODS.
ESPECIALLY IF THEY HAD
THE POWER TO ALTER
THEIR FORM AT WILL
AND COMMAND
GREAT ENERGY.
IN FACT,
THEY COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
TAKEN FOR ANYTHING ELSE.
READY TO REVERSE
POLARITY, MR. SULU?
COMPUTED AND STANDING
BY TO GENERATE, SIR.
ACTIVATE ALL UNITS.
[CRASH]
NO GOOD, MR. SPOCK.
WE DIDN'T
EVEN FAZE IT.
WE'RE STILL
LOCKED TIGHT.
CUT POWER, MR. SULU.
LIEUTENANT, WE MUST
RESTORE COMMUNICATIONS
WITH THE LANDING PARTY.
WELL, I'M WORKING,
SIR, BUT I CAN'T DO
ANYTHING WITH THIS.
OH?
WELL, I MIGHT BE
ABLE TO RIG UP
A SUBSPACE
BYPASS CIRCUIT.
GOOD. DO SO.
SENSOR REPORT, MR. KYLE.
WELL, I'VE LOCATED THE
LANDING PARTY, SIR, BUT
ONE OF THEM SEEMS SEPARATED
FROM THE OTHER FOUR.
AND APOLLO?
I'VE JUST PICKED UP READINGS
FOR OUR OWN PEOPLE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, HERE'S SOMETHING.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
A RADIATED ENERGY PULSATION
COMING FROM THE PLANET.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS, SIR.
ORIGIN?
I CAN'T SEEM TO
PINPOINT IT, SIR.
I WOULD SUGGEST,
MR. SULU, THAT
IF YOU CANNOT FIND OUT
WHERE THE POWER SOURCE IS,
YOU SHOULD FIND OUT
WHERE IT IS NOT.
A SIMPLE PROCESS
OF ELIMINATION.
THE WHOLE PLANET, SIR?
YES, SIR.
THE WHOLE PLANET.
OH, IT'S LOVELY.
I'VE KNOWN OTHER WOMEN--
DAPHNE, CASSANDRA...
BUT NONE MORE
BEAUTIFUL THAN YOU.
ARE YOU FRIGHTENED
OF ME?
FRIGHTENED?
NO, I DON'T
THINK SO.
OF COURSE, A
GIRL DOESN'T GO
WALKING WITH A--
A GOD?
ALL RIGHT. A GOD.
EVERY DAY.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE OTHERS?
ARTEMIS, HERA?
THEY RETURNED
TO THE COSMOS...
ON THE WINGS
OF THE WIND.
YOU MEAN THEY DIED?
NO,
NOT AS YOU
UNDERSTAND IT.
WE'RE IMMORTAL,
WE GODS...
BUT THE EARTH CHANGED.
YOUR FATHERS CHANGED.
THEY TURNED AWAY UNTIL
WE WERE ONLY MEMORIES.
A GOD CANNOT SURVIVE
AS A MEMORY.
WE NEED LOVE,
ADMIRATION, WORSHIP,
AS YOU NEED FOOD.
YOU REALLY THINK
YOU'RE A GOD?
IN A REAL SENSE,
WE WERE GODS.
WE HAD THE POWER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
WE COULD HAVE STRUCK
OUT FROM OLYMPUS
AND DESTROYED.
WE HAVE NO WISH
TO DESTROY,
SO WE CAME HOME AGAIN.
IT WAS AN EMPTY PLACE
WITHOUT WORSHIPERS,
BUT WE HAD NO
STRENGTH TO LEAVE,
AND WE WAITED,
ALL OF US,
THROUGH THE LONG YEARS.
BUT YOU SAID
THE OTHERS DIDN'T DIE.
EVEN FOR A GOD,
THERE'S A POINT
OF NO RETURN.
HERA WAS FIRST.
SHE STOOD IN FRONT
OF THE TEMPLE
AND SPREAD HERSELF
UPON THE WIND--
THINNER AND THINNER...
UNTIL ONLY THE
WIND REMAINED...
BUT I KNEW
YOU WOULD COME--
YOU STRIVING, BICKERING,
FOOLISHLY BRAVE HUMANS.
I KNEW YOU WOULD COME
TO THE STARS ONE DAY.
OF ALL THE GODS,
I KNEW, AND I WAITED--
WAITED FOR YOU TO COME
SIT BY MY SIDE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
EVEN 5,000 YEARS AGO,
THE GODS TOOK
MORTALS TO THEM
TO LOVE, TO CARE FOR,
LIKE ZEUS TOOK
LETO, MY MOTHER.
WE WERE GODS
OF PASSION...
OF LOVE.
THERE IS
A REPEATED OCCURRENCE
OF REGISTRATIONS,
A REGULAR
PULSATING PATTERN
OF RADIATED ENERGY.
UNQUESTIONABLY, AN
IMMENSELY POWERFUL
FIELD OF ENERGY
IS BEING GENERATED
AROUND HERE
SOMEWHERE.
BUT WE'RE JUST
HAVING DIFFICULTY
FOCUSING ON IT.
APOLLO HAS NO
DIFFICULTY FOCUSING.
HE TAPS THAT
ENERGY, MR. SCOTT.
SIR, SOME CREATURES
CAN GENERATE AND
CONTROL ENERGY
WITH NO HARM
TO THEMSELVES--
THE ELECTRIC EEL
ON EARTH,
THE GIANT DRY
WORM OF ANTOS 4,
THE FLUFFY--
NOT THE WHOLE
ENCYCLOPEDIA, CHEKOV.
THE CAPTAIN REQUIRES
COMPLETE INFORMATION.
SPOCK'S CONTAMINATING
THIS BOY, JIM.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT HE--APOLLO--
TAPS A FLOW
OF ENERGY
AND CHANNELS IT
THROUGH HIS BODY?
THAT WOULD SEEM
MOST LIKELY, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, I THINK
YOU'VE EARNED YOUR PAY
FOR THE WEEK,
BUT WHERE IS THE
SOURCE OF THAT POWER?
NUMBER ONE ON OUR LIST
OF THINGS TO DO.
IS THAT ALL
YOU HAVE TO OFFER?
YES, EXCEPT MY ESTIMATION
FOR HIS PHYSICAL CONDITION.
IN SPITE OF APOLLO'S
BAG OF TRICKS,
HE COMES UP
ESSENTIALLY NORMAL
WITH JUST A FEW
VARIATIONS.
HOWEVER,
THERE'S AN EXTRA
ORGAN IN HIS CHEST
THAT I CAN'T EVEN
MAKE A GUESS ABOUT.
BONES,
IS IT POSSIBLE--
JIM.
WHERE IS LIEUTENANT
PALAMIS?
SHE IS NO LONGER
OF ANY CONCERN TO YOU.
YOU BLOODTHIRSTY SARACEN,
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE WITH HER?
SCOTTY!
NOT GOOD.
SEVERE SHOCK.
ALL RIGHT, MISTER...
YOU WANTED WORSHIPERS?
YOU'VE GOT ENEMIES.
YOU WANT US
TO BOW DOWN--
[THUNDER]
[GAGGING]
YOU WILL LEARN
DISCIPLINE.
YOU WILL LEARN...
CHEKOV,
GIVE ME A HAND.
TAKE CARE OF SCOTTY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN?
WHERE'S APOLLO?
HE DISAPPEARED AGAIN
LIKE THE CAT IN
THAT RUSSIAN STORY.
DON'T YOU MEAN
THE ENGLISH STORY,
THE CHESHIRE CAT?
CHESHIRE? NO, SIR.
MINSK PERHAPS, BUT--
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
SIR, THERE IS
SOMETHING I NOTICED.
APOLLO
LOOKED VERY STRANGE
WHEN HE DISAPPEARED,
TIRED OR IN PAIN.
I DON'T KNOW IF
IT MEANS ANYTHING.
WHERE HE GOES,
MR. CHEKOV--
THAT MIGHT VERY WELL
MEAN SOMETHING.
[MOANING]
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
I CAN'T GET MY ARM
TO MOVE.
SOME NEURAL
DAMAGE.
WE'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
HOW?
WELL, LET'S ASSUME...
5,000 YEARS AGO,
CREATURES LIKE
OUR FRIEND APOLLO
DID INDEED VISIT EARTH
AND FORM THE BASIS OF
THE GREEK CLASSIC MYTHS.
MAKES SENSE.
MOST MYTHOLOGY HAS
ITS BASIS IN FACT.
NOW, IF I REMEMBER
MY ANCIENT LEGENDS,
THE GODS, AFTER
EXPENDING ENERGY,
REQUIRED REST,
EVEN AS WE HUMANS.
AND APOLLO'S GONE--
AFTER ATTACKING
YOU AND MR. SCOTT.
YOU THINK MAYBE HE'S OFF
SOMEWHERE RECHARGING
HIS ENERGY CELLS?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
REMEMBER, HE'S
KEEPING A FORCE
FIELD ON THE SHIP,
AND HE'S EXPENDING
ENERGY DOWN HERE.
YOU SAID HE LOOKED
PAINED AND TIRED
WHEN HE DISAPPEARED.
IF WE CAN WEAR HIM
OUT, OVERWORK HIM,
THAT MIGHT DO IT.
THE TROUBLE WITH
OVERWORKING HIM IS
THAT IT CAN GET US KILLED.
IF WE CAN PROVOKE HIM
SO THAT HE STRIKES
ONE OF US AGAIN,
THERE'S A CHANCE
THAT HE'LL BE
DRAINED ENOUGH
SO THE REST OF
US CAN JUMP HIM.
I STILL SAY IT
CAN GET US KILLED.
NOT ALL OF
US, BONES.
WHEN HE COMES BACK,
IT'S A CHANCE
WE'LL HAVE TO TAKE.
PROGRESS REPORT.
I'M CONNECTING THE
BYPASS CIRCUIT NOW, SIR.
IT SHOULD TAKE
ANOTHER HALF-HOUR.
SPEED IS ESSENTIAL,
LIEUTENANT.
MR. SPOCK, I
HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING
LIKE THIS IN YEARS.
IF IT ISN'T DONE
JUST RIGHT,
I COULD BLOW THE ENTIRE
COMMUNICATIONS SYSTEM.
IT'S VERY DELICATE
WORK, SIR.
I CAN THINK OF
NO ONE
BETTER EQUIPPED
TO HANDLE IT,
MISS UHURA.
PLEASE PROCEED.
YES, SIR...
RIGHT AWAY.
PROGRESS, MR. SULU?
SECTORS 1 THROUGH 25
CHARTED AND EXAMINED.
NO CHANCE AT ALL
OF POWER ORIGINATING
IN THOSE AREAS.
CONTINUE THE SEARCH.
AYE, SIR.
14-B BY
26 INDEXED.
- MR. KYLE.
- YES, SIR.
WE'RE UNABLE
TO BREAK COMPLETELY LOOSE
FROM THIS FORCE FIELD,
BUT WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO PUNCH SOME HOLES
THROUGH IT.
WHAT FOR, SIR?
TO SHOOT THROUGH.
IT MIGHT ALSO RELIEVE
LIEUTENANT UHURA'S
COMMUNICATIONS PROBLEM.
TAKE THESE EQUATIONS
TO THE NUCLEAR
ELECTRONICS LAB.
I WANT THEM
TO WORK ON THE PROBLEM
OF NEGATING THE FORCE FIELD
IN SELECTED AREAS.
NOW, IT MIGHT BE DONE
BY GENERATING A STRONG
PINPOINT CHARGE OF M-RAYS
ON SOME OF THESE
SELECTED WAVELENGTHS
AND TYING THEM IN
WITH THE COMBINED OUTPUT
OF ALL OUR ENGINES.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
COME HERE!
I KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO ESCAPE ME.
IT'S USELESS.
I KNOW EVERYTHING
YOU DO.
I TRIED TO BE
COMPASSIONATE
TOWARD YOUR KIND.
YOU KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT OUR KIND.
YOU KNOW ONLY
OUR REMOTE ANCESTORS
WHO TREMBLED
BEFORE YOUR TRICKS.
YOUR TRICKS
DON'T FRIGHTEN US.
NEITHER DO YOU.
WE'VE COME A LONG
WAY IN 5,000 YEARS.
AND YOU'RE STILL OF
THE SAME NATURE.
I COULD SWEEP YOU
OUT OF EXISTENCE
WITH A WAVE OF MY HAND
AND BRING YOU BACK AGAIN.
I CAN GIVE LIFE
OR DEATH.
WHAT ELSE DOES MANKIND
DEMAND OF ITS GODS?
MANKIND HAS NO
NEED FOR GODS.
WE FIND THE ONE
QUITE ADEQUATE.
WE SHALL NOT
DEBATE, MORTAL.
I OFFER YOU ETERNAL
REST AND HAPPINESS
ACCORDING TO
THE ANCIENT WAYS.
I ASK LITTLE IN RETURN,
BUT WHAT I ASK
FOR, I INSIST UPON.
APPROACH ME.
I SAID APPROACH ME!
WE'RE BUSY.
Look out
for the girl.
YOU WILL GATHER
LAUREL LEAVES,
LIGHT THE ANCIENT FIRES,
KILL A DEER,
MAKE YOUR
SACRIFICES TO ME!
APOLLO HAS SPOKEN!
GO!
GATHER LAUREL LEAVES?
YOU MUST BE JOKING!
HA HA HA HA!
"KILL A DEER."
THAT'S THE
FUNNIEST THING THAT
I EVER HEARD!
"KILL A DEER."
THAT'S THE
FUNNIEST THING THAT
I EVER HEARD!
GO AHEAD!
HA HA HA!
LIEUTENANT, GET BACK.
YOU SHALL REAP THE
REWARDS OF YOUR INSOLENCE!
WE'RE TIRED OF
YOUR PHONY FIREWORKS!
MORTAL, YOU
HAVE EARNED THIS!
NO, DON'T!
LIEUTENANT!
A FATHER DOESN'T
DESTROY HIS CHILDREN.
YOU SAID YOU WERE GENTLE
AND UNDERSTANDING.
LIEUTENANT!
HOW CAN THEY WORSHIP
YOU IF YOU HURT THEM?
LIEUTENANT.
APOLLO, PLEASE.
YOU KNOW SO MUCH OF LOVE.
PLEASE DON'T HURT THEM.
PLEASE?
I SHALL BE LENIENT
WITH YOU...
FOR HER SAKE.
YOU WILL MAKE PLANS
TO BRING THE REST
OF YOUR PEOPLE DOWN.
BE SURE YOUR
ARTISANS BRING TOOLS.
YOU WILL NEED HOMES.
AND YOU'LL SUPPLY
THE HERDS OF SHEEP,
AND THE PIPES WE WILL PLAY,
AND THE SIMPLE SKINS
WE'LL WEAR FOR CLOTHES?
YOU WILL DISMANTLE
YOUR SHIP
FOR THE SUPPLIES
YOU NEED,
AND I'LL CRUSH
ITS EMPTY HULL.
I HAVE BEEN TOO PATIENT.
I SHALL BE
PATIENT NO LONGER.
CAPTAIN,
WE'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING!
WE WERE
DOING SOMETHING
UNTIL OUR BRAVE LADY
STEPPED IN AND SAVED US.
GOT ANY MORE
GOOD IDEAS, JIM?
YES, I HAVE, ONE MORE.
AND IT DEPENDS ON
THE LIEUTENANT'S LOYALTY.
IF SHE FAILS US,
WE BETTER GET USED
TO HERDING GOATS.
FOOLS.
I OFFER THEM
MORE THAN THEY COULD KNOW,
NOT JUST A WORLD,
BUT ALL THAT MAKES IT UP.
MAN THINKS HE'S PROGRESSED.
THEY'RE WRONG.
HE'S MERELY
FORGOTTEN THOSE THINGS
WHICH GAVE LIFE
MEANING.
YOU'LL ALL BE
PROVIDED FOR,
CARED FOR, HAPPY.
THERE IS AN ORDER OF THINGS
IN THIS UNIVERSE.
YOUR SPECIES HAS DENIED IT.
I COME TO RESTORE IT...
AND FOR YOU...
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
THE SENSITIVITY
TO UNDERSTAND,
I OFFER YOU MORE
THAN YOUR WILDEST DREAMS
HAVE EVER IMAGINED.
YOU'LL BECOME THE MOTHER
OF A NEW RACE OF GODS.
YOU'LL INSPIRE
THE UNIVERSE.
ALL MEN WILL
REVERE YOU...
ALMOST AS A GOD
YOURSELF,
AND I SHALL LOVE YOU
FOR TIME WITHOUT END,
WORLDS WITHOUT END.
YOU SHALL COMPLETE
ME AND I YOU.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE,"
COME IN.
"ENTERPRISE," COME IN.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE,"
COME IN. KIRK TO--
CAROLYN.
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO HER?
SCOTTY,
I'LL FIND OUT.
PERHAPS
IF I ASSISTED...
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
22, SIR.
THEN I'D BETTER
HANDLE IT.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
OH, YES,
I'M ALL RIGHT.
I HAVE A MESSAGE
FOR YOU.
COME OVER THERE.
WELL?
HE WANTS US
TO LIVE IN PEACE.
HE WANTS
TO PROVIDE FOR US.
HE'LL GIVE US
EVERYTHING WE EVER WANTED,
AND HE CAN
DO IT, TOO.
ALL RIGHT, LIEUTENANT,
YOU CAN COME DOWN
FROM MOUNT OLYMPUS NOW.
YOU'VE GOT
WORK TO DO.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE THRIVES ON LOVE,
WORSHIP, ATTENTION.
YES?
WE CAN'T GIVE HIM
THAT WORSHIP.
NONE OF US CAN,
ESPECIALLY YOU.
WHAT?
SPURN HIM.
REJECT HIM.
YOU MUST.
YOU'RE SPECIAL
TO HIM.
YES...
I LOVE HIM.
LIEUTENANT...
ALL OUR LIVES,
HERE AND ON THE SHIP,
DEPEND ON YOU.
NO, NOT ON ME.
ON YOU, LIEUTENANT!
REJECT HIM,
AND WE HAVE A CHANCE
TO SAVE OURSELVES.
ACCEPT HIM,
AND YOU CONDEMN
ALL OF US TO SLAVERY,
NOTHING LESS
THAN SLAVERY.
WE MIGHT NEVER GET
HELP THIS FAR OUT,
OR PERHAPS THE THOUGHT
OF SPENDING AN ETERNITY
BENDING KNEE
AND TENDING SHEEP
APPEALS TO YOU.
OH, BUT YOU
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE'S KIND, AND HE WANTS
THE BEST FOR US...
AND HE'S SO LONELY.
WHAT YOU ASK
WOULD BREAK HIS HEART.
HOW CAN I?
GIVE ME YOUR HAND.
YOUR HAND.
NOW FEEL THAT.
HUMAN FLESH AGAINST
HUMAN FLESH.
WE'RE THE SAME.
WE SHARE
THE SAME HISTORY,
THE SAME HERITAGE,
THE SAME LIVES.
WE'RE TIED TOGETHER
BEYOND ANY UNTYING.
MAN OR WOMAN,
IT MAKES NO DIFFERENCE.
WE'RE HUMAN.
WE COULDN'T
ESCAPE FROM EACH OTHER,
EVEN IF WE WANTED TO.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT,
LIEUTENANT,
BY REMEMBERING WHO
AND WHAT YOU ARE--
A BIT OF FLESH AND BLOOD
AFLOAT IN A UNIVERSE
WITHOUT END,
AND THE ONLY THING
THAT'S TRULY YOURS
IS THE REST
OF HUMANITY.
THAT'S WHERE
OUR DUTY LIES.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YES.
YES, I UNDERSTAND.
HE'S CALLING ME.
LIEUTENANT...
YOU HAVE
YOUR ORDERS...
AND YOUR DUTY.
YES, SIR,
MY ORDERS
AND MY DUTY.
I THINK WE CAN
TRY IT NOW, SIR.
"ENTERPRISE"
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE PINPOINTED
A POWER SOURCE
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE
WHICH SEEMS TO HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE FORCE FIELD.
IS THERE A STRUCTURE
OF SOME SORT NEAR YOU?
THERE IS INDEED,
MR. SPOCK.
THE POWER EMANATES
FROM THERE.
VERY GOOD.
HOW ARE YOU DOING
ON THE FORCE FIELD?
WE CAN NEGATE
SECTIONS OF IT,
CREATING OPENINGS
THROUGH WHICH WE CAN
FIRE OUR PHASER BANKS.
WELL, THAT
OUGHT TO DO IT.
HAVE MR. SULU
LOCK ALL PHASER BANKS
ONTO THE STRUCTURE.
FIRE ON MY ORDER ONLY
AND CUT IT FINE.
WE'LL BE STANDING
NEARBY.
CAPTAIN, I WOULD RECOMMEND
A DISCREET DISTANCE.
I'D LOVE TO OBLIGE
YOU, MR. SPOCK,
BUT WE'RE NOT
ALL TOGETHER.
BESIDES,
WE HAVE APOLLO
TO DEAL WITH.
IF THAT STRUCTURE
IS THE SOURCE
OF HIS POWER,
I WANT TO KNOW
WHERE HE IS
WHEN WE ATTACK IT.
KIRK OUT.
BONES, DO YOU THINK
THAT MYSTERIOUS ORGAN
IN APOLLO'S CHEST
COULD HAVE SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE TRANSMISSION
OF ENERGY?
IT DOESN'T SERVE
ANY OTHER PURPOSE
I KNOW OF.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE
GOT TO WAIT UNTIL
CAROLYN COMES BACK
BEFORE WE FIRE
ON THE TEMPLE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN TO HER
IF HE WERE SUDDENLY
ATTACKED.
SHE MIGHT
GET KILLED.
YES, I KNOW. I KNOW.
SCOTTY, WE'LL WAIT.
I MUST SAY, APOLLO...
THE WAY YOU APE
HUMAN BEHAVIOR
IS REMARKABLE,
BUT THERE ARE
SOME OTHER THINGS
I MUST KNOW--
YOUR EVOLUTIONARY
PATTERNS
AND YOUR
SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT.
MY WHAT?
I'M SURE THEY'RE UNIQUE.
I'VE NEVER ENCOUNTERED
A SPECIMEN LIKE YOU BEFORE.
I AM APOLLO.
I'VE CHOSEN YOU.
WELL, I'M SURE THAT'S VERY
FLATTERING, BUT I MUST GET
ON WITH MY WORK NOW.
YOUR WORK?
I'M A SCIENTIST.
MY PARTICULAR SPECIALTY
IS ANCIENT CIVILIZATIONS,
RELICS, AND MYTHS.
SURELY, YOU KNOW
I'VE ONLY BEEN
STUDYING YOU.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
YOU LOVE ME.
LOVE YOU?
OH, BE LOGICAL.
I'M NOT SOME SIMPLE
SHEPHERDESS YOU CAN AWE.
WHY, I COULD
NO MORE LOVE YOU
THAN I COULD LOVE
A NEW SPECIES
OF...BACTERIA.
CAROLYN!
I FORBID YOU TO GO.
I ORDER YOU TO STAY!
IS THAT THE SECRET
OF YOUR POWER OVER WOMEN--
THE THUNDERBOLTS
YOU THROW?
[WIND HOWLING]
[THUNDER]
WHAT THE DEVIL
IS THAT?
[BEEPING]
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
AN ATMOSPHERIC DISTURBANCE
IN YOUR AREA.
STAND BY YOUR PHASERS,
MR. SPOCK.
PREPARE TO FIRE ON
MY SIGNAL. KIRK OUT.
[THUNDER]
CAPTAIN,
WE'VE GOT TO GO
AND FIND HER!
AND WE'VE GOT
TO BE HERE WHEN
HE COMES BACK!
BUT WHAT IF HE DOESN'T?
WHAT IF--
SCOTTY, JUST HOLD ON!
[THUNDER]
AAH!
NO!
- CAPTAIN!
- ALL RIGHT.
NO! AAH!
THE TEMPLE
IS HIS POWER SOURCE.
LET'S BRING HIM
BACK TO IT.
GET TO COVER.
MR. SPOCK,
FIRE THOSE PHASERS.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE TOO CLOSE.
FIRE THOSE PHASERS!
THAT'S AN ORDER,
MR. SPOCK!
ALL PHASER BANKS,
FIRE!
NO!
STOP!
STOP, I SAY!
ALL PHASER BANKS,
MAINTAIN FIRING RATE!
MORE POWER
TO THE SHIELDS.
STOP!
[THUNDER]
SCOTTY!
STOP, I SAY!
[THUNDER]
I COMMAND IT!
ALL BANKS MAINTAIN
FIRING RATE.
MAINTAINING, SIR.
STOP!
I WOULD HAVE CHERISHED YOU,
CARED FOR YOU.
I WOULD HAVE LOVED YOU
AS A FATHER LOVES HIS CHILDREN.
DID I ASK SO MUCH?
WE'VE OUTGROWN YOU.
YOU ASKED
FOR SOMETHING
WE CAN NO
LONGER GIVE.
CAROLYN...
I LOVED YOU.
I WOULD HAVE MADE
A GODDESS OF YOU.
I'VE SHOWN YOU
MY OPEN HEART.
SEE WHAT YOU'VE
DONE TO ME.
ZEUS...
HERMES...
HERA...
APHRODITE...
YOU WERE RIGHT.
ATHENA...
THE TIME HAS PASSED.
THERE IS NO ROOM
FOR GODS.
FORGIVE ME,
MY OLD FRIENDS.
TAKE ME.
[ECHOES]
[CRYING]
I WISH WE HADN'T
HAD TO DO THIS.
SO DO I.
THEY GAVE US
SO MUCH.
THE GREEK
CIVILIZATION,
MUCH OF OUR CULTURE
AND PHILOSOPHY
CAME FROM A WORSHIP
OF THOSE BEINGS.
IN A WAY, THEY BEGAN
THE GOLDEN AGE.
WOULD IT HAVE
HURT US, I WONDER...
JUST TO HAVE GATHERED
A FEW LAUREL LEAVES?