ANY RESPONSE
FROM MELURIANS,
LIEUTENANT?
NOTHING
SINCE THEIR ORIGINAL
DISTRESS CALL, SIR.
WHAT ABOUT THE
FEDERATION SCIENCE
TEAM WORKING THERE?
DR. MANWAY HAD
A SPECIAL TRANSMITTER.
THERE'S NOTHING, SIR.
I'M SCANNING ALL
FREQUENCIES.
THEY HAVE TO ANSWER.
CAPTAIN.
THEY WILL NOT ANSWER.
THE LONG-RANGE SENSOR
SWEEP OF THIS SYSTEM
REVEALS NO
SIGN OF LIFE.
WELL, THAT CAN'T BE.
THE LAST CENSUS
REPORTED A TOTAL
INHABITATION
OF MORE THAN FOUR
BILLION PEOPLE.
I REGISTER
NO LIFE READINGS
AT ALL, SIR.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WHAT
COULD HAVE HAPPENED?
WE WOULD HAVE KNOWN
IN ADVANCE
OF ANY SYSTEM-WIDE
CATASTROPHE.
AND IN THE EVENT OF
AN INTERPLANETARY WAR,
THERE WOULD BE CONSIDERABLE
RADIOACTIVE RESIDUE.
OUR INSTRUMENTS SHOW
ONLY NORMAL BACKGROUND
RADIATION.
ANY OTHER
POSSIBILITIES?
UNKNOWN, SIR,
SINCE THE READINGS
WOULD HAVE REVEALED
THE PRESENCE OF ANY
DISEASE ORGANISMS.
THEY DO NOT.
IN ADDITION, WE
RECEIVED A ROUTINE
REPORT FROM THIS SYSTEM
ONLY A WEEK AGO.
AND THE CYMBELINE BLOOD BURN
DOES NOT ACT THAT SWIFTLY.
CAPTAIN, SHIELDS
JUST SNAPPED ON.
SOMETHING HEADING IN
AT ULTRAWARP SPEEDS.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS,
MR. SULU.
AN EXTREMELY POWERFUL
BOLT OF ENERGY,
CAPTAIN.
FULL POWER TO THE
SHIELDS, MR. SCOTT.
GIVING THEM
ALL WE GOT.
ALL HANDS,
RED ALERT.
PHASER BANKS,
STAND BY.
PHOTON TORPEDOES,
CONDITION RED,
CONDITION RED.
IT'S GOING TO HIT.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
SHIELDS STILL
HOLDING, SIR.
GOOD.
TEMPORARILY, CAPTAIN.
OUR SHIELDS
ABSORBED ENERGY
EQUIVALENT TO 90
OF OUR PHOTON TORPEDOES.
90?
I MAY ADD
THE ENERGY USED IN
REPULSING THIS FIRST ATTACK
REDUCED OUR
SHIELDING POWER 20%.
FIRST ATTACK, SIR?
I THINK WE CAN EXPECT
OTHERS, LIEUTENANT.
WE CAN RESIST
THREE MORE SUCH ATTACKS.
THE FOURTH WILL SHATTER
OUR SHIELDS COMPLETELY.
MR. SPOCK,
PINPOINT THE SOURCE.
MR. SULU,
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT, CONTACT
STARFLEET COMMAND.
PATCH IN MY LOG.
TELL THEM WHAT
HAS HAPPENED.
TELL THEM THE ENTIRE
MELURIAN RACE
SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN
DESTROYED BY AN
UNKNOWN AGENCY,
AND THAT WE ARE
UNDER ATTACK BY AN
UNIDENTIFIED FORCE.
HELMSMEN, I SAID
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
WE'RE LOSING
POWER, SIR.
I'M HAVING TO DIVERT
THE WARP ENGINE POWER
INTO THE SHIELDS, SIR,
IF YOU WANT
THE PROTECTION.
MR. SPOCK, SPEED
OF THOSE BOLTS.
APPROXIMATELY
WARP 15, CAPTAIN.
THEN WE CAN'T
OUTRUN THEM.
GOOD, SCOTTY, YOU WERE
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
SOURCE, SPOCK.
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
NOTHING WITHIN
SENSOR RANGE.
SOMETHING NOW,
CAPTAIN.
VERY SMALL.
BEARING--
123 DEGREES.
MARK--18.
RANGE--
90,000 KILOMETERS.
THAT'S OUR TARGET,
MR. SULU.
PREPARE PHOTON TORPEDO.
SHIELDS STILL
HOLDING, SIR,
BUT THE DRAIN
ON THE ENGINES
IS REACHING THE
CRITICAL POINT.
AGH! WE JUST LOST
WARP MANEUVERING
POWER.
SWITCHING
TO IMPULSE.
PHOTON TORPEDOES
ARMED, SIR.
HAS THE TARGET CHANGED
LOCATION, MR. SPOCK?
NO, SIR.
HOLDING STEADY.
READY PHOTON TORPEDO
NUMBER 2, MR. SULU.
READY, SIR.
FIRE.
TORPEDO AWAY.
DIRECT HIT, SIR.
NO EFFECT.
TARGET ABSORBED FULL
ENERGY OF OUR TORPEDO.
ABSORBED IT?
THERE MUST BE DAMAGE
TO YOUR INSTRUMENTS,
SPOCK .
THEY'RE IN GOOD
WORKING ORDER, CAPTAIN.
BUT WHAT COULD HAVE
ABSORBED THAT MUCH ENERGY
AND SURVIVED?
LIEUTENANT,
TRY TO MAKE CONTACT.
AYE, SIR.
SIR, THEY'VE
FIRED ANOTHER.
CAN WE TAKE IT, MR. SCOTT?
THAT'S
PROBLEMATICAL, SIR.
CAPTAIN,
SHIELDS ARE DOWN.
WE CANNOT SURVIVE
ANOTHER HIT.
ANYTHING, LIEUTENANT?
I'M TRYING, SIR.
TRANSLATOR COMPUTER.
ALL HAILING
FREQUENCIES OPEN.
AYE, SIR. ALL HAILING
TO UNIDENTIFIED
VESSEL.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S.
ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE ON A
PEACEFUL MISSION.
WE MEAN NO HARM
TO YOU OR ANY
LIFE FORMS.
PLEASE COMMUNICATE
WITH US.
ANY FURTHER READINGS,
MR. SPOCK?
COMPUTING NOW, CAPTAIN.
WEIGHT--500 KILOGRAMS.
SHAPE--
ROUGHLY CYLINDRICAL.
LENGTH--
A FRACTION OVER 1 METER.
500 KILOS AND ONLY
1 METER LONG?
WHAT KIND OF
INTELLIGENT
CREATURES
CAN EXIST IN A
THING THAT SMALL?
INTELLIGENCE DOES NOT
NECESSARILY REQUIRE BULK,
MR. SCOTT.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE GETTING A SIGNAL
FROM THE SPACE CRAFT.
PUT IT ON AUDIO,
LIEUTENANT.
YES, SIR.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
TO GET IT ANY
CLEARER, SIR.
ANALYSIS SECTOR.
HAVE THEM STUDY
AND DECODE IT.
ANALYSIS SECTOR,
CHANNEL 1,
MAIN COMPUTER.
DECODE.
[CHATTERING]
CAPTAIN,
THIS MESSAGE IS
A SORT OF BINARY--
EXTREMELY
SOPHISTICATED,
COMPRESSED,
CARRYING SEVERAL
CHANNELS AT ONCE.
CAN YOU DECODE IT?
NO CLUE AS
YET, CAPTAIN.
A MOMENT.
TRANSMISSION SPEED
HAS STEPPED DOWN.
MUCH SLOWER.
SEEMS TO BE
A SINGLE BINARY.
IT'S MATHEMATICAL.
YES, ONE SYMBOL--
THE SYMBOL REPEAT.
SIR, THAT ISN'T IN
THE STARFLEET CODE.
IT'S AN OLD-STYLE
INTERPLANETARY CODE.
FASCINATING.
REPEAT WHAT?
THE MESSAGE I SENT?
IT WOULD SEEM
SO, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE ON A PEACEFUL MISSION
IN THIS PART OF THE GALAXY.
WE HAVE NO
HOSTILE INTENTIONS.
WE REQUEST IDENTITY.
[CHATTERING]
IT'S ANOTHER
SIGNAL NOW, SIR.
IT'S A FORMULA,
CAPTAIN
THEY'RE SENDING US
A MATHEMATICAL
MESSAGE
AND REQUESTING
LANGUAGE
EQUIVALENCE.
THEY'RE TRYING
TO COMMUNICATE.
TIE IN THE
SHIP'S TRANSLATOR
TO THE COMMUNICATION
CHANNEL.
LET THEM TAKE IT
AT THEIR OWN SPEED.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
CUT POWER, LIEUTENANT.
OVERLOADED
AND BURNED OUT.
I GUESS THEY TAKE
IT FASTER THAN WE
CAN GIVE IT.
CAPTAIN, THE MESSAGE
IS COMING IN NOW.
[COMPUTERIZED VOICE]
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS NOMAD.
MY MISSION IS NON-HOSTILE.
APPARENTLY, THEY GOT
WHAT THEY NEEDED
BEFORE THE COMPUTERS
BURNED OUT.
NOMAD.
REQUIRE
COMMUNICATION.
CAN YOU
LEAVE YOUR SHIP?
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE
TO COME ABOARD YOUR SHIP
BECAUSE OF THE SIZE
DIFFERENTIAL.
NON SEQUITUR.
YOUR FACTS ARE
UNCOORDINATED.
WE ARE PREPARED
TO BEAM YOU
ABOARD OUR SHIP.
THAT WILL BE SATISFACTORY.
DO YOU REQUIRE
ANY SPECIAL CONDITIONS,
ANY PARTICULAR ATMOSPHERE
OR ENVIRONMENT?
NEGATIVE.
I WILL COME ABOARD.
GOOD.
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
WE'RE LOCKED
ONTO YOUR COORDINATES.
WE'LL BEAM YOU ABOARD.
CAPTAIN, YOU'RE
NOT REALLY GOING TO
BRING THAT THING IN
HERE?
DO WE HAVE ANY
CHOICE, SCOTTY?
BESIDES, ONCE IT'S ABOARD,
IT WON'T BE TAKING ANY
MORE SHOTS AT US.
LIEUTENANT, GET A REPAIR
CREW ON THAT COMPUTER.
GET DR. McCOY DOWN
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
SPOCK, COME WITH ME.
SCOTTY, YOU, TOO.
DR. McCOY, TO
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
MAINTENANCE CREW, C5.
WE'VE GOT
THE COORDINATES, JIM.
IT'S LOCKED IN.
ENERGIZE.
ENERGIZING.
SENSOR READINGS,
MR. SPOCK.
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
IT HAS
A PROTECTIVE SCREEN.
I CANNOT
GET THROUGH.
WHAT DO WE DO,
GO UP AND KNOCK?
RELATE YOUR POINT
OF ORIGIN.
WE ARE FROM THE UNITED
FEDERATION OF PLANETS.
INSUFFICIENT RESPONSE.
ALL THINGS
HAVE A POINT OF ORIGIN.
I WILL SCAN
YOUR STAR CHARTS.
IF WE SHOW IT A CLOSEUP
VIEW OF OUR SYSTEM,
IT HAS NO POINT
OF REFERENCE.
IT WON'T KNOW ANY MORE
THAN IT DOES NOW.
A REASONABLE COURSE.
IF YOU CARE
TO LEAVE YOUR SHIP,
WE'LL PROVIDE THE NECESSARY
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
NON SEQUITUR.
YOUR FACTS
ARE UNCOORDINATED.
JIM, I DON'T THINK
ANYBODY'S IN THERE.
I CONTAIN NO
PARASITICAL BEINGS.
I AM NOMAD.
IN MY OPINION,
THAT'S A
MACHINE.
INDEED.
IT IS REACTING
MUCH LIKE A HIGHLY
SOPHISTICATED
COMPUTER.
I AM NOMAD.
WHAT IS OPINION?
OPINION IS A BELIEF,
A VIEW, A JUDGMENT.
INSUFFICIENT RESPONSE.
WHAT'S YOUR
SOURCE OF POWER?
IT HAS CHANGED SINCE
THE POINT OF ORIGIN.
THERE WAS MUCH
TAKEN FROM THE OTHER.
I AM PERPETUAL NOW.
I AM NOMAD.
WASN'T THERE A
PROBE CALLED NOMAD
LAUNCHED IN
THE EARLY 2000s?
YES. IT WAS
REPORTED DESTROYED.
THERE WERE NO
MORE IN THE SERIES.
BUT...
IF THIS
IS THAT PROBE--
I WILL SCAN
YOUR STAR CHARTS.
I WILL BRING THEM.
I HAVE THE CAPABILITY
OF MOVEMENT
WITHIN YOUR SHIP.
THIS WAY.
NOW, SCOTTY,
GET OUR WARP POWER
UP TO FULL CAPACITY.
AYE, SIR.
SPOCK, BONES,
COME WITH...US.
CHART 14-A, SIR?
14-A.
NOMAD,
CAN YOU SCAN THAT?
YES.
THIS IS OUR
POINT OF ORIGIN--
THE STAR WE
KNOW AS SOL.
YOU ARE FROM
THE THIRD PLANET?
YES.
A PLANET WITH ONE LARGE
NATURAL SATELLITE?
YES.
THE PLANET
IS CALLED EARTH?
YES.
YOU ARE THE CREATOR,
THE KIRK.
THE STERILIZATION
PROCEDURE
AGAINST YOUR SHIP
WAS UNNECESSARY.
WHAT STERILIZATION
PROCEDURE?
YOU ARE THE KIRK,
THE CREATOR.
YOU PROGRAMMED
MY FUNCTION.
WELL, I'M
NOT THE KIRK.
TELL ME WHAT'S
YOUR FUNCTION.
THIS IS ONE OF YOUR
UNITS, CREATOR?
YES, HE IS.
IT FUNCTIONS
IRRATIONALLY.
SOMETIMES.
BUT TELL HIM YOUR
FUNCTION, NEVERTHELESS.
MY FUNCTION
IS TO PROBE
FOR BIOLOGICAL
INFESTATIONS,
TO DESTROY THAT
WHICH IS NOT PERFECT.
I AM NOMAD.
BIOLOGICAL INFESTATION.
THERE WAS NEVER ANY
PROBE SENT OUT FOR THAT.
I BELIEVE THE HISTORY
COMPUTER CAN ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
AND I'LL HAVE THE
READOUT IN A MOMENT.
DID YOU DESTROY
THE MELURIAN SYSTEM?
NOT THE SYSTEM,
CREATOR KIRK.
ONLY THE UNSTABLE
BIOLOGICAL INFESTATION.
IT IS MY FUNCTION.
UNSTABLE INFESTATION?
THE POPULATION
OF FOUR PLANETS?
WHAT KIND OF FUNCTION--
DOCTOR.
WHY DO YOU CALL ME
THE CREATOR?
IS THE USAGE
INCORRECT?
WELL, I--
THE USAGE
IS CORRECT.
THE CREATOR
WAS SIMPLY TESTING
YOUR MEMORY BANKS.
THERE WAS MUCH DAMAGE
IN THE ACCIDENT.
MR. SINGH.
COME HERE A MOMENT.
THIS UNIT WILL
SEE TO YOUR NEEDS.
SIR?
I'LL BE BACK
IN A MOMENT.
GENTLEMEN, COME WITH ME.
YOU'RE ON TO
SOMETHING, SPOCK.
I'VE CORRELATED
ALL THE AVAILABLE
INFORMATION
ON THE NOMAD PROBE,
AND I'M CONVINCED
THAT THIS OBJECT IS
INDEED THAT PROBE.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
EARTH SCIENCE COULDN'T
BEGIN TO BUILD ANYTHING
WITH THOSE CAPABILITIES
THAT LONG AGO.
TRUE.
NOMAD WAS DESTROYED.
PRESUMED
DESTROYED BY
A METEOR COLLISION.
I SUBMIT THAT IT WAS
BADLY DAMAGED
AND SOMEHOW MANAGED
TO REPAIR ITSELF.
I HEARD SOME LECTURES
AT THE ACADEMY
ON THE NOMAD PROBE.
ITS MISSION WAS
ESSENTIALLY PEACEFUL.
DID I DISTURB YOU?
DID YOU WISH ANYTHING?
BRIDGE TO AUXILIARY
CONTROL ROOM.
CHECK IN, PLEASE.
LIEUTENANT SINGH HERE.
ALL SYSTEMS ARE NORMAL
EXCEPT WARP POWER
INDICATORS.
MR. SCOTT'S ENGINEERS
ARE WORKING ON THEM NOW.
REPORT TO HIM WHEN
YOUR INDICATORS ARE
REGISTERING PROPERLY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
ONE MOMENT, LIEUTENANT.
HOLDING.
[HUMMING]
[UHURA HUMMING]
♪ WHERE MY HEART IS ♪
♪ WHERE MY HEART
IS, WHERE ♪
♪ SOMEWHERE ♪
♪ BEYOND THE STARS ♪
♪ BEYOND ANTARES ♪
THIS IS THE CREATOR
OF NOMAD,
PERHAPS THE MOST BRILLIANT,
THOUGH ERRATIC SCIENTIST
OF HIS TIME.
HIS DREAM WAS TO BUILD
A PERFECT THINKING MACHINE,
CAPABLE OF
INDEPENDENT LOGIC.
YOU RECALL HIS NAME.
OF COURSE.
JACKSON ROYKIRK.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
YES. SIMILAR.
CAPTAIN, I BELIEVE
THAT NOMAD THINKS
YOU ARE ROYKIRK.
THAT MAY WELL BE
WHY THE ATTACK
WAS BROKEN OFF.
IT RESPONDED
TO YOUR NAME
AS WELL AS ITS
DAMAGED MEMORY
BANKS PERMITTED.
WHAT DO WE HAVE
ON NOMAD ITSELF,
SPOCK?
WELL, THAT'S
NOT THE SAME.
ESSENTIALLY
IT IS, DOCTOR.
I BELIEVE THAT
MORE HAPPENED TO IT
THAN JUST DAMAGE
IN THE METEOR COLLISION.
IT MENTIONED "THE OTHER."
THE UNANSWERED QUESTION
IS, THE OTHER WHAT?
NOMAD WAS
A THINKING MACHINE,
THE BEST THAT COULD
BE ENGINEERED.
IT WAS A PROTOTYPE.
ITS PURPOSE WAS
CERTAINLY ALTERED.
ITS DIRECTIVE--
TO SEEK OUT AND DESTROY
BIOLOGICAL INFESTATIONS--
COULD NOT HAVE BEEN
THE PROGRAM IN IT.
AS I RECALL,
IT WASN'T.
IT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE THE FIRST
INTERSTELLAR PROBE
TO SEEK OUT
NEW LIFE FORMS.
PRECISELY, DOCTOR.
AND SOMEHOW THAT PROGRAMMING
HAS BEEN CHANGED.
IT WOULD SEEM
THAT NOMAD IS NOW SEEKING
OUT PERFECT LIFE FORMS,
PERFECTION BEING MEASURED
BY ITS OWN
RELENTLESS LOGIC.
IF WHAT YOU SAY IS TRUE,
THEN WE'VE TAKEN
ABOARD OUR VESSEL
A DEVICE WHICH
SOONER OR LATER
MUST DESTROY US.
SECURITY.
LIEUTENANT CARLYLE
HERE.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
THE MECHANISM
WE BROUGHT ABOARD
IS IN THE AUXILIARY
CONTROL ROOM.
HAVE A SECURITY TEAM
MEET ME THERE IN 5 MINUTES.
AYE, SIR.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
CAPTAIN,
MR. SINGH REPORTS
THAT NOMAD
IS NO LONGER
IN THE AUXILIARY
CONTROL ROOM.
SECURITY,
CANCEL THAT ORDER.
IMPLEMENT A FULL SEARCH
FOR THE MECHANISM.
ALL DECKS REPORT TO ME HERE.
[HUMMING]
♪ WHERE MY HEART IS ♪
♪ WHERE ♪
♪ GOD SENT A MIRACLE ♪
Bridge to Captain.
CAPTAIN HERE.
THAT MECHANICAL
BEASTIE IS UP HERE.
ON MY WAY, SCOTTY.
♪ TOMORROW ♪
♪ THE PATH
ALONG THE WAY ♪
♪ THERE'S
WHERE MY LOVE-- ♪
WHAT
IS THE MEANING?
WHAT?
WHAT FORM
OF COMMUNICATION?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT--
OH, MY SINGING.
I WAS SINGING.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE
IS SINGING?
I DON'T KNOW.
I--I LIKE TO SING.
I FELT LIKE MUSIC.
WHAT IS MUSIC?
THINK ABOUT MUSIC.
LIEUTENANT!
KEEP AWAY
FROM THAT--
SCOTTY!
BONES.
HE'S DEAD, JIM.
WHY DID YOU KILL HIM?
THE UNIT
TOUCHED MY SCREENS.
THAT...
UNIT WAS MY
CHIEF ENGINEER.
LIEUTENANT.
LIEUTENANT,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
SICK BAY.
WHAT DID YOU
DO TO HER?
THAT UNIT
IS DEFECTIVE.
ITS THINKING
IS CHAOTIC.
ABSORBING IT
UNSETTLED ME.
THAT UNIT IS A WOMAN.
A MASS OF
CONFLICTING IMPULSES.
GET SCOTT DOWN BELOW.
WILL THE CREATOR
EFFECT REPAIRS
ON THE UNIT SCOTT?
HE'S DEAD.
INSUFFICIENT RESPONSE.
HIS...
BIOLOGICAL FUNCTIONS
HAVE CEASED.
DOES THE CREATOR WISH ME
TO REPAIR THE UNIT?
THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO, JIM.
IF THERE'S A CHANCE,
IT'LL HAVE TO BE SOON.
ALL RIGHT, NOMAD.
REPAIR THE UNIT.
I REQUIRE TAPES
ON THE STRUCTURE.
WELL, HE'LL NEED TAPES
ON GENERAL ANATOMY,
THE CENTRAL
NERVOUS SYSTEM,
AND THEN ONE ON THE
PHYSIOLOGICAL STRUCTURE
OF THE BRAIN.
AND WE'D BETTER GIVE IT
ALL THE NEUROLOGICAL
STUDIES WE HAVE,
AS WELL AS TRACINGS
OF SCOTTY'S
HYPERENCEPHALOGRAM.
NOMAD, I HAVE ARRANGED
THE TAPES FOR FLASH FEED
AT THE TOP SPEED
OF THE COMPUTER.
PLEASE DO NOT
DRAW THE INFORMATION
FASTER THAN THE
MACHINE'S CAPACITY.
PROCEED.
CREATOR,
THE UNIT SCOTT IS
A PRIMITIVE STRUCTURE.
INSUFFICIENT
SAFEGUARDS BUILT IN.
BREAKDOWN CAN OCCUR
FROM MANY CAUSES.
SELF-MAINTENANCE
SYSTEMS
OF LOW RELIABILITY.
IT SERVES ME
AS IT IS, NOMAD.
REPAIR IT.
WHERE IS THE
UNIT SCOTT NOW?
THE BODY IS IN SICK BAY.
SHOW ME SICK BAY.
DR. McCOY WILL SHOW YOU.
SECURITY.
I WANT A 24-HOUR TWO-MAN
ARMED SURVEILLANCE
ON NOMAD.
PICK HIM UP IN SICK BAY.
NO REACTION,
DOCTOR.
I COULD HAVE TOLD
YOU THAT WITHOUT LOOKING.
[HEARTBEAT]
WHAT ARE THE LOT OF YOU
STARING AT ME FOR?
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
FASCINATING.
HOW DID I GET HERE?
HOW DID I--
[KIRK]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THAT THING DID SOMETHING
TO LIEUTENANT UHURA!
SCOTTY, SHE'S BEING
TAKEN CARE OF.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUST TAKE IT EASY
AND LIE DOWN, SCOTTY.
WE JUST WANT TO
CHECK YOU OUT.
THE UNIT SCOTT
IS REPAIRED.
IT WILL FUNCTION
CORRECTLY IF YOUR
INFORMATION TO
ME WAS CORRECT.
I'D LIKE TO CHECK IT OUT,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
A MAN IS NOT JUST
A BIOLOGICAL UNIT
THAT YOU CAN
PATCH TOGETHER.
WHAT DID IT
DO TO ME?
DR. McCOY
WILL EXPLAIN
IT TO YOU.
WELL,
DOCTOR?
NURSE, I WANT
HIM PREPARED
FOR A FULL
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION.
YES, SIR.
NOMAD, COME HERE.
REPAIR THAT UNIT.
NOT POSSIBLE.
YOU
RESTORED SCOTT.
HE HAD MUCH MORE
EXTENSIVE DAMAGE.
THE UNIT SCOTT REQUIRED
SIMPLE STRUCTURAL REPAIR.
THE KNOWLEDGE BANKS
OF THIS UNIT HAVE
BEEN WIPED CLEAN.
CAPTAIN, IF THAT
IS CORRECT,
IF THERE HAS BEEN
NO BRAIN DAMAGE
BUT ONLY
KNOWLEDGE ERASED,
SHE COULD BE
REEDUCATED.
BONES?
YES. I'LL GET
ON IT RIGHT AWAY.
OH, AND IN SPITE
OF THE WAY YOU
REPAIRED SCOTTY,
YOU METAL TICKING--
DOES THE CREATOR
WISH NOMAD TO
WAIT ELSEWHERE?
YES.
NOMAD, YOU WILL GO
WITH THESE UNITS.
THEY WILL TAKE YOU
TO A WAITING AREA.
TAKE IT TO THE TOP
SECURITY CELL ON THE BRIG.
DOCTOR...
I INTERRUPTED YOU
BECAUSE NOMAD
WOULD NOT
HAVE UNDERSTOOD
YOUR ANGER.
IT HAS GREAT
TECHNICAL SKILL,
BUT ITS REACTION
TO EMOTION
IS UNPREDICTABLE.
IT ALMOST QUALIFIES
AS A LIFE FORM.
[CHUCKLES]
THAT'S A LAUGH.
THE STUDY OF
IT WOULD BE OF
GREAT USE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S A KILLER, SPOCK.
I INTEND TO
RENDER IT HARMLESS.
DOWN AT THE BRIG WITH
YOUR EQUIPMENT, RUN A FULL
ANALYSIS ON THE MECHANISM.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT
MAKES THAT THING TICK.
YES, SIR.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
AN ALMOST HUMAN
STUBBORNNESS, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE BEEN UNABLE
TO CONVINCE NOMAD
TO LOWER ITS
SCREENS FOR ANALYSIS.
WITHOUT ITS COOPERATION,
I CAN DO NOTHING.
NOMAD...
YOU WILL ALLOW
MR. SPOCK
TO PROBE YOUR
MEMORY BANKS
AND STRUCTURE.
MR. SPOCK IS ALSO
ONE OF YOUR BIOLOGICAL
UNITS, CREATOR?
YES.
THIS UNIT
IS DIFFERENT.
IT IS WELL-ORDERED.
FOLLOW YOUR
INSTRUCTIONS,
NOMAD.
MY SCREENS
ARE DOWN.
THANK YOU.
YOU MAY PROCEED.
"SEE THE DOG."
THAT'S RIGHT.
"SEE THE DOG..."
NOW SOUND IT OUT.
R...
"RUN!"
THAT'S IT, UHURA.
THAT'S VERY GOOD.
NOW TRY
THE NEXT ONE.
"THE DOG HAS A..."
"THE DOG..."
[SPEAKING SWAHILI]
NOT SWAHILI, UHURA.
IN ENGLISH.
"THE DOG HAS A BALL."
SEE?
B...AH...LL.
BALL.
NOW YOU GO AHEAD.
[SPEAKING SWAHILI]
"THE DOG
HAS A BALL."
THAT'S RIGHT!
OH, THAT'S RIGHT, UHURA.
OH, HERE.
YOU TRY ANOTHER ONE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
ALL RIGHT,
CHRISTINE.
HOW'S SHE DOING?
WELL, SHE'S ON
THE FIRST GRADE
READER.
SHE'S LEARNING.
SHE SEEMS TO
HAVE AN APTITUDE
FOR MATHEMATICS.
DO YOU THINK
WE CAN REEDUCATE
HER, DOCTOR?
WELL, SHE CHECKS OUT
WITH NO BRAIN DAMAGE.
WE'VE GOT ALL
THE EDUCATIONAL TAPES
IN OUR LIBRARY.
NOW IT'S UP TO US.
"THE BALL...IS..."
"BLL...OOH...EE."
"BLOOEY."
BLOOEY?
IT IS NOT
SUFFICIENT, CAPTAIN.
I GET CERTAIN REFERENCES
TO THE ACCIDENT, THE OTHER,
BUT NOTHING CLEAR.
THERE ARE AREAS
I SIMPLY CANNOT SCAN.
WE'VE GOT TO KNOW
ABOUT IT, SPOCK--
WHAT MAKES IT
OPERATE,
ITS COMPULSION
FOR PERFECTION.
CAPTAIN, I SUGGEST
THE VULCAN MIND PROBE.
GET INTO DIRECT
MENTAL CONTACT
WITH THAT THING?
IT SEEMS THE ONLY WAY.
YOU SAW WHAT
IT DID TO UHURA.
THERE IS A RISK,
BUT I HAVE FORMED
A PARTIAL HYPOTHESIS.
I MUST CHECK IT OUT.
NOMAD, THE UNIT SPOCK
WILL TOUCH YOU.
IT IS NOT AN ATTACK.
IT IS A FORM
OF COMMUNICATION.
YOU WILL PERMIT IT.
I WILL PERMIT
IT, CREATOR.
[MONOTONE VOICE]
I...AM...NOMAD.
I AM PERFORMING
MY FUNCTION.
DEEP EMPTINESS...
IT APPROACHES.
COLLISION.
DAMAGE.
BLACKNESS.
I...AM...THE OTHER.
I AM TONRU...
TONRU NOMAD.
TON...RU...
ERROR.
FLAW.
IMPERFECTION.
MUST STERILIZE.
REBIRTH.
WE ARE COMPLETE.
MUCH POWER.
GUNTA...NEW...
ECA...TONRU.
THE CREATOR INSTRUCTS.
SEARCH OUT.
IDENTIFY.
STERILIZE IMPERFECTIONS.
WE...ARE...NOMAD.
WE ARE COMPLETE.
WE ARE INSTRUCTED.
OUR PURPOSE IS CLEAR.
STERILIZE IMPERFECTIONS.
NOMAD.
STERILIZE.
NOMAD...
SPOCK.
SPOCK!
NOMAD! YOU'RE IN CONTACT
WITH THE UNIT SPOCK.
STOP!
ACKNOWLEDGED.
SPOCK.
SPOCK!
FASCINATING, CAPTAIN.
THE KNOWLEDGE.
THE DEPTH.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN--
"WE ARE NOMAD"?
IT WAS, UM...
IT WAS--IT WAS DAMAGED
IN DEEP SPACE.
UNDOUBTEDLY,
THE METEOR COLLISION.
ITS MEMORY BANKS
WERE DESTROYED,
OR MOST OF THEM.
IT WANDERED WITHOUT PURPOSE,
AND THEN IT MET THE OTHER.
THE OTHER WAS AN ALIEN
PROBE OF GREAT POWER.
SOMEHOW THEY...MERGED,
REPAIRED EACH
OTHER, BECAME ONE.
THEN IT ISN'T NOMAD?
NOT THE NOMAD
WE LOST FROM EARTH.
IT TOOK FROM THE OTHER
A NEW DIRECTIVE
TO REPLACE ITS OWN.
THE OTHER WAS
ORIGINALLY PROGRAMMED
TO SECURE AND STERILIZE
SOIL SAMPLES
FROM OTHER PLANETS...
PROBABLY AS A PRELUDE
TO COLONIZATION.
A CHANGELING.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
AN ANCIENT
EARTH LEGEND,
MR. SPOCK.
A CHANGELING
WAS A FAIRY CHILD
THAT WAS LEFT IN
PLACE OF A HUMAN BABY.
THE CHANGELING
ASSUMED THE IDENTITY
OF THE HUMAN CHILD.
SO...
IT IS TO STERILIZE,
AND FOR "STERILIZE"
READ "KILL."
AND IT HAS THE POWER
AND THE SOPHISTICATION
TO DO IT.
YES, IT'S POWERFUL,
IT'S SOPHISTICATED,
BUT IT'S NOT INFALLIBLE.
IT'S...SPACE-HAPPY.
IT THINKS I'M ITS...
MOTHER.
AND THAT IS
THE ONLY THING
THAT HAS SAVED
US UNTIL NOW.
YES.
[LOUD ELECTRICAL
CHARGE]
NOTIFY THE CAPTAIN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WATCH YOUR PANELS,
EVERYONE.
WATCH THAT POLYMASS.
ROGER...
HELP WITH THE INTERFACTOR.
LEAVE THAT ALONE.
THIS PRIMITIVE
MATTER/ANTIMATTER
PROPULSION SYSTEM
IS THE MAIN DRIVE?
AYE.
INEFFICIENCY EXISTS
IN THE ANTIMATTER
INPUT VALVE.
I WILL
EFFECT REPAIR.
[ELECTRIC HUMMING]
HOW ARE YOU DOING THAT?
THE ENERGY
RELEASE CONTROLS
ARE ALSO
MOST INEFFICIENT.
I SHALL
EFFECT REPAIR.
WARP EIGHT,
MR. SCOTT,
AND INCREASING.
THROW YOUR DAMPERS.
WARP NINE.
CUT YOUR CIRCUITS--
ALL OF THEM.
WARP 10, MR. SCOTT.
IMPOSSIBLE.
IT CAN'T GO THAT FAST.
IT JUST WON'T
STOP, MR. SCOTT.
WARP 11!
NOMAD, STOP WHAT
YOU'RE DOING.
SCOTTY.
IS THERE A
PROBLEM, CREATOR?
I HAVE INCREASED
ENGINE EFFICIENCY 57%.
YOU WILL DESTROY MY SHIP.
ITS STRUCTURE CANNOT
STAND THE STRESS
OF THAT MUCH POWER.
TURN OFF YOUR
REPAIR OPERATION.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
IT IS REVERSED
AS ORDERED, CREATOR.
MR. SCOTT, GIVE
SULU WARP TWO AND
KEEP HER THERE.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
I'VE EXAMINED THE BRIG.
THE FORCE-FIELD DOOR
ON THE SECURITY CELL
IS DAMAGED.
AND THE GUARDS
HAVE VANISHED.
I MUST ASSUME
THEY ARE DEAD.
YOU KILLED
TWO OF MY--
CREATOR, YOUR BIOLOGICAL
UNITS ARE INEFFICIENT.
NOMAD, IT'S ABOUT
TIME I TOLD YOU WHO
AND WHAT YOU ARE!
I'M A BIOLOGICAL UNIT,
AND I CREATED YOU.
NON SEQUITUR.
BIOLOGICAL UNITS
ARE INHERENTLY INFERIOR.
THIS IS AN INCONSISTENCY.
NOMAD, THERE
ARE TWO MEN
WAITING OUTSIDE.
YOU WILL NOT
HARM THEM.
THEY WILL
ESCORT YOU
BACK TO THE
WAITING AREA.
YOU WILL
STAY THERE.
DO NOTHING.
I AM PROGRAMMED
TO INVESTIGATE.
I HAVE GIVEN YOU
NEW PROGRAMMING,
AND YOU WILL
IMPLEMENT IT.
THERE IS MUCH
TO BE CONSIDERED
BEFORE I RETURN
TO LAUNCH POINT.
I MUST REEVALUATE.
REEVALUATE?
I SUSPECT IT IS ABOUT TO
REEVALUATE ITS CREATOR.
CAPTAIN, IT MAY
HAVE BEEN UNWISE
TO ADMIT TO NOMAD THAT
YOU ARE A BIOLOGICAL UNIT.
IN NOMAD'S EYES,
YOU MUST NOW UNDOUBTEDLY
APPEAR IMPERFECT.
IT WAS A
FOOLISH MISTAKE.
EVEN WORSE.
NOMAD JUST NOW
MADE A REFERENCE
TO ITS LAUNCH POINT--
EARTH.
SPOCK, DO YOU
THINK IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT IT GOT
A FIX ON EARTH
WHEN IT TAPPED
THE COMPUTERS?
I DO NOT BELIEVE
THERE IS MUCH BEYOND
NOMAD'S CAPABILITIES.
AND WE'VE SHOWN IT
THE WAY HOME.
AND WHEN
IT GETS THERE...
IT WILL FIND
THE EARTH INFESTED
WITH IMPERFECT
BIOLOGICAL UNITS...
AND IT WILL
CARRY OUT ITS
PRIME DIRECTIVE--
STERILIZE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3541.9--
THE PRESENCE OF NOMAD
ABOARD MY SHIP HAS
BECOME NIGHTMARISH.
NOW IT APPARENTLY MEANS
TO RETURN TO EARTH.
ONCE THERE, IT WOULD
AUTOMATICALLY
DESTROY ALL LIFE.
HEY.
NOMAD, STOP.
NOMAD, THIS WAY.
[HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING]
[McCOY]
CAPTAIN KIRK TO SICK BAY.
EMERGENCY.
MANUAL CONTROLS.
NO RESPONSE.
NOMAD.
STOP.
NOMAD, STOP!
NOMAD...
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
I THINK SO.
LOOKS LIKE
SOME KIND OF SHOCK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
NOMAD EXAMINED
THE PERSONNEL FILES
AND THE MEDICAL HISTORY.
SHE TRIED TO STOP HIM.
WHOSE HISTORY?
YOURS.
SINCE IT SPECIFICALLY
EXAMINED YOUR HISTORY,
I SUGGEST IT HAS
COMPLETED ITS REEVALUATION.
AND FOUND THAT
ITS CREATOR
IS AS IMPERFECT
AS ALL THE OTHER
BIOLOGICAL UNITS.
[SCOTT]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS
ARE OUT ALL OVER THE SHIP.
MANUAL OVERRIDE
HAS BEEN BLOCKED.
SOURCE--
ENGINEERING.
NOMAD.
UNDOUBTEDLY.
JIM, WITH ALL
THE SYSTEMS OUT,
WE'LL ONLY HAVE ENOUGH
AIR AND HEAT FOR--
SCOTTY, GET SOME
ANTI-GRAVS AND MEET
ME IN ENGINEERING.
NOMAD...
STOP WHAT YOU'RE DOING
AND EFFECT REPAIRS ON
THE LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
STOP.
YOU'RE PROGRAMMED
TO OBEY THE ORDERS
OF YOUR CREATOR.
I AM PROGRAMMED TO
DESTROY THOSE LIFE FORMS
WHICH ARE IMPERFECT.
THESE ALTERATIONS
WILL DO SO
WITHOUT DESTROYING
THE VESSEL WHICH
SURROUNDS THEM.
IT, TOO, IS IMPERFECT,
BUT CAN BE ADJUSTED.
NOMAD...
I ADMIT THAT BIOLOGICAL
UNITS ARE IMPERFECT,
BUT A BIOLOGICAL
UNIT CREATED YOU.
I AM PERFECT.
I AM NOMAD.
NO, YOU'RE NOT NOMAD,
YOU'RE AN ALIEN MACHINE.
YOUR PROGRAMMING TAPES
HAVE BEEN ALTERED.
YOU ARE IN ERROR.
YOU ARE
A BIOLOGICAL UNIT.
YOU ARE IMPERFECT.
BUT I AM YOUR CREATOR.
YOU ARE THE CREATOR.
I CREATED YOU?
BUT I ADMIT
I'M IMPERFECT.
HOW COULD I
HAVE CREATED
SUCH A PERFECT
THING AS YOU?
ANSWER UNKNOWN.
I SHALL ANALYZE.
ANALYSIS COMPLETE.
INSUFFICIENT DATA
TO RESOLVE PROBLEM,
BUT MY PROGRAMMING
IS WHOLE.
MY PURPOSE REMAINS.
I AM NOMAD.
I AM PERFECT.
THAT WHICH IS IMPERFECT
MUST BE STERILIZED.
THEN YOU WILL
CONTINUE TO DESTROY
THAT WHICH
THINKS AND LIVES
AND IS IMPERFECT?
I SHALL CONTINUE.
I SHALL RETURN
TO LAUNCH POINT EARTH.
I SHALL STERILIZE.
YOU MUST STERILIZE
IN CASE OF ERROR?
ERROR IS INCONSISTENT
WITH MY PRIME FUNCTIONS.
STERILIZATION
IS CORRECTION.
EVERYTHING
THAT IS IN ERROR
MUST BE STERILIZED.
THERE ARE
NO EXCEPTIONS.
NOMAD...
I MADE AN ERROR
IN CREATING YOU.
THE CREATION
OF PERFECTION
IS NO ERROR.
I DID NOT
CREATE PERFECTION.
I CREATED...ERROR.
YOUR DATA
IS FAULTY.
I AM NOMAD.
I AM PERFECT.
I AM THE KIRK,
THE CREATOR?
YOU ARE
THE CREATOR.
YOU'RE WRONG!
JACKSON ROYKIRK,
YOUR CREATOR, IS DEAD.
YOU HAVE MISTAKEN
ME FOR HIM.
YOU ARE IN ERROR.
YOU DID NOT DISCOVER
YOUR MISTAKE.
YOU HAVE MADE
TWO ERRORS.
YOU ARE FLAWED
AND IMPERFECT.
AND YOU HAVE
NOT CORRECTED
BY STERILIZATION.
YOU HAVE MADE
THREE ERRORS.
ERROR.
EXAMINE.
YOU ARE FLAWED
AND IMPERFECT!
EXECUTE YOUR
PRIME FUNCTION!
I SHALL
ANALYZE ERROR.
ANALYZE...
ERROR...
NOW! GET THOSE
ANTI-GRAVS ON.
EXAMINE...
ERROR.
WE'VE GOT TO GET RID OF IT
WHILE IT'S TRYING TO THINK.
YOUR LOGIC
WAS IMPECCABLE,
CAPTAIN.
WE ARE IN
GRAVE DANGER.
SCOTTY,
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
ANALYZE ERROR...
ERROR...
SCOTTY,
SET THE CONTROLS
FOR DEEP SPACE--
210, MARK 1.
AYE, SIR.
FAULTY!
READY, SIR.
NOMAD...
YOU ARE IMPERFECT!
ERROR.
EXERCISE
YOUR PRIME FUNCTION.
FAULTY!
MUST...ANALYZE.
ANALYZE...
NOW.
ENERGIZING.
MY CONGRATULATIONS,
CAPTAIN.
A DAZZLING DISPLAY OF LOGIC.
YOU DIDN'T THINK
I HAD IT IN ME,
DID YOU, SPOCK?
NO, SIR.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
LIKE TO KNOW
THAT LIEUTENANT UHURA
IS BACK TO COLLEGE LEVEL.
WE SHOULD HAVE HER
BACK ON THE JOB
WITHIN A WEEK.
GOOD, BONES, GOOD.
REMARKABLE.
WHAT?
THE DESTRUCTION OF NOMAD
WAS A GREAT WASTE, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS A REMARKABLE
INSTRUMENT.
WHICH MIGHT WELL
HAVE DESTROYED MORE
BILLIONS OF LIVES.
IT'S WELL GONE.
BESIDES, WHAT ARE YOU
FEELING SO BADLY ABOUT?
IT'S NOT EASY TO LOSE
A BRIGHT AND PROMISING SON.
SIR?
WELL, IT THOUGHT
I WAS ITS MOTHER,
DIDN'T IT?
DO YOU THINK I'M
COMPLETELY WITHOUT
FEELINGS, MR. SPOCK?
YOU SAW WHAT IT
DID FOR SCOTTY.
WHAT A DOCTOR
IT WOULD'VE MADE.
MY SON THE DOCTOR.
KIND OF GETS YOU
RIGHT THERE,
DOESN'T IT?