( thunder crashing )
We believe what you say,
Captain Kirk,
but our position
has not altered.
The Halkan Council
cannot permit your federation
to mine dilithium crystals
on our planet.
We have shown the council
historical proof
that our missions
are peaceful.
We accept that your federation
is benevolent at present,
but the future
is always in question.
Our dilithium crystals
represent awesome power.
Wrongful use of that power,
even to the extent
of the taking of one life,
would violate our history
of total peace.
To prevent that,
we would die, Captain,
as a race if necessary.
I admire your ethics
and hope to prove ours.
( thunder crashing )
Kirk to Enterprise.
Spock here.
Report on magnetic storm,
Mr. Spock.
Standard ion type, Captain,
but quite violent and...
and unpredictable.
Rough ride?
If we stay.
Stand by to beam up
landing party.
Plot an extended orbit
to clear disturbance. Kirk out.
Comply, Mr. Sulu.
Aye, sir.
When may we
resume discussion?
The council
will meditate further,
but do not be hopeful
of any change.
( thunder crashing )
Captain.
You do have the might
to force the crystals
from us, of course.
But we won't.
Consider that.
Enterprise.
Transporter room,
energize.
( thunder crashing )
Trouble, sir.
Spock was right.
It was a rough trip.
SPOCK:
At norm, Mr. Kyle.
Controls at neutral.
Yes, sir.
Status of mission,
Captain?
No change.
Standard procedure,
Captain?
Mr. Sulu, you will program
phaser barrage on Halkan cities.
SULU:
Yes, Mr. Spock.
Their military capability,
Captain?
None.
Regrettable that this society
has chosen suicide.
Mr. Kyle,
you were instructed
to compensate
during the ion storm.
But I tried to--
Carelessness with the equipment
cannot be tolerated.
But, Mr. Spock,
I tried--
Your agonizer.
No, Mr. Spock.
Your agonizer, please.
No, Mr. Spock!
I tried.
I really tried.
( Kyle groaning )
( gasping )
KIRK:
Space--the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission--
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no man has gone before.
( main theme playing )
( dramatic music playing )
KIRK:
Captain's log,
stardate unknown.
During an ion storm,
my landing party has beamed
back to the Enterprise
and found it and
the personnel aboard changed.
The ship is subtly
altered physically.
Behavior and discipline
has become brutal, savage.
Mr. Scott, the storm
has caused some minor damage
in your section.
There are also injuries
requiring your attention,
Doctor.
Well, gentlemen?
Mr. Spock?
SPOCK: Yes?
The power beam jumped
for a moment, sir,
just as the landing party
was about to materialize.
I never saw it happen before.
Due to your error,
Mr. Kyle?
No, Mr. Spock.
Before.
Possibly a result
of the severe storm.
Captain, did you feel
any abnormal effects?
Yes.
Dr. McCoy,
you better look us over.
That was a rough beam-up.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Spock.
Have those transporter circuits
checked.
Captain,
what is all this?
How did we get
into--
Not now. Not now.
( dramatic music playing )
What is this?
Everything's all messed up
and changed around,
out of place.
Captain,
what's happened?
No, not everything.
That spot--
I spilled acid there
a year ago.
Jim,
what in blazes is--
I don't know.
It's our Enterprise,
but it isn't.
Maybe...
Maybe what,
Captain?
Any of you feel dizzy
when we were
in the transporter beam...
Yes.
...when we first
materialized?
I did.
It happened twice.
First we were
in our own transporter chamber,
then we faded.
And then,
when we finally materialized,
we were here,
wherever this is.
Captain, the transporter chief
mentioned a surge of power.
The transporter lock
might have been affected
by the ion storm
and we just materialized
somewhere else.
Yes, here.
Not our universe,
not our ship.
Something...
parallel,
a parallel universe
coexisting with ours
on another dimensional plane.
Everything's duplicated...
almost.
Another Enterprise.
Spock with a beard.
Another Captain Kirk,
another Dr. McCoy, an--
An exchange.
Another--
If we're here...
Then our counterparts
must have been transporting up
at the exact same time.
Similar storms on both universes
disrupted the circuits.
We're here, and they're--
on our Enterprise,
probably asking
the same questions.
Are we in another universe,
and if so, how do we
get back to our own?
They'll use the computer,
and we have to.
What about the Halkans?
We can't let them
be destroyed.
Scotty, can you
buy me some time?
Get below and short out
the main phaser couplings.
They'll think the storm
blew the standby circuits.
Aye, sir.
Then get on this technology.
It's all we have to work with
if we want to get back home.
The intercom
may be monitored.
Use your communicators
for private messages.
Subfrequency
and scramble.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant.
Yes, sir.
Get up to your post.
Run today's communication
from Starfleet Command.
I want to know my exact orders
and options, if any.
Yes, sir.
Bones.
Captain, I-I'm...
Uhura, you're the only one
who can do it.
I'll be right there.
Yes, sir.
Bones, let's take a look
at the library.
We have a lot to learn.
Mr. Chekov, phaser setting
for planetary target A.
Coordinates 7-1-2.
Stroke 4, Mr. Sulu.
Port batteries locked.
Still no interest,
Uhura?
Hm?
I could change your mind.
You are away
from your post, mister.
Is the captain here?
Is Spock here?
When the cat's away...
Communications status.
No storm damage, sir.
All stations report normal.
( softly )
You're ordered
to annihilate the Halkans
unless they comply.
No alternative.
SULU:
Phasers locked
on target A, Captain.
Approaching optimum range.
Commence fire, Captain?
Captain?
Stand by, Mr. Sulu.
I've, uh...been ordered
to check phaser couplings
for possible damage
by the storm.
Do you have authorization
from security, sir?
Captain's orders.
I'll have to check with
Security Chief Sulu, sir.
Never mind.
I'll attend to it.
( intercom whistles )
Kirk here.
Phaser report, sir.
No damage.
Very good.
Thank you, Mr. Scott.
Kirk out.
Planet's rotation
is carrying primary target
beyond arc of phaser lock.
Shall I correct orbit
to new firing position?
No.
Lock on to secondary city.
Aye, sir.
Lieutenant Uhura,
contact the Halkan Council.
I wish to talk to them again.
Yes, sir.
Captain?
This is a new race.
They offer other things of value
besides dilithium crystals.
But it is clear that we cannot
expect their cooperation.
They have refused the Empire.
Command procedure dictates
that we provide
the customary example.
Secondary target now moving
beyond our phaser lock.
Put phasers
on standby, Mr. Sulu.
A serious breach
of orders, Captain.
I have my reasons,
and I'll make them clear
to you
in my own good time.
Captain, I have the leader
of the Halkan Council
waiting on channel B.
KIRK:
It is useless to resist us.
We do not resist you.
You have 12 hours
to consider your position.
12 years, Captain Kirk,
or 12,000--
we are ethically compelled
to deny your demand
for our dilithium crystals,
for you would use their power
to destroy.
We will level your planet
and take what we want.
That is destruction.
You will die as a race.
To preserve what we are.
We will not argue.
12 hours. No more.
Close communications.
Turn phasers off.
Aye, sir.
12 hours, Captain?
That is unprecedented.
I shall be
in my quarters.
Lieutenant Uhura,
have Dr. McCoy and Mr. Scott
meet me there.
( console beeps )
Captain,
you have placed yourself
in a most grave
position.
This conduct
must be reported.
You're at liberty
to do so, Mr. Spock.
Deck five, sir?
( suspenseful music playing )
So you die, Captain,
and we all move up in rank.
No one will question
the assassination of a captain
who has disobeyed prime orders
of the Empire.
Captain's log, supplemental.
I command an Enterprise
where officers
apparently employ
private henchmen
among the crew,
where assassination
of superiors
is a common means
of advancing in rank.
Your men, Captain.
Easy, Farrell.
I did your job.
Ask the captain.
Sir?
Yes, he did your job.
Smart boy, switching
to the top dog.
Get him out of here.
Mr. Chekov was going to
make me a chief, sir.
You could make me
an officer.
All right,
you're working for me.
A commission?
You're in line.
You might even make captain.
Yes, sir.
Ohh!
Not on my ship.
The booth
for this one, sir?
Yes, the booth.
Carry on.
Here. Here.
What's this?
It's called blood.
Watch your step.
The officers move up
by assassination.
Chekov tried it on me.
Mr. Sulu is
security chief,
like the ancient
Gestapo.
And my sick bay
is a chamber of horrors.
Two of my assistants
were betting
on the tolerance
of an injured man,
how long it would take him
to pass out from the pain.
Report on technology.
Mostly variations
in instrumentation.
Nothing
I can't handle.
Star readings?
Everything's exactly
where it should be,
except us.
Let's find out
where we stand.
Computer.
MALE VOICE:
Ready.
This is the captain.
Record security research,
to be classified
under my voice print
or Mr. Scott's.
Recorded.
Produce all data relevant
to the recent ion storm.
Correlate following hypothesis--
could a storm of such magnitude
cause a power surge
in the transporter circuits,
creating a momentary
interdimensional contact
with a parallel universe?
Affirmative.
At such a moment,
could persons in each universe,
in the act of beaming,
transpose
with their counterparts
in the other universe?
Affirmative.
Could conditions necessary
to such an event
be created artificially
using the ship's power?
Affirmative.
Record procedure.
( clicks )
( beeps )
Scotty, can you do it?
Not by myself.
I'll need help.
And you'd be too conspicuous.
I'm a doctor, not an engineer.
Now you're an engineer.
I'll have to tap the power
we need from the warp engines
and balance it
for the four of us.
Jim, the way
this ship is run,
what kind of people are we
in this universe?
Let's find out.
Computer.
( beeps )
Ready.
Read out official record
of current command.
Captain James T. Kirk
succeeded to command
ISS Enterprise
through assassination
of Captain Christopher Pike.
First action--suppression
of Gorlan uprising
through destruction
of rebel home planet.
Second action--execution
of 5000 colonists on Vega 9.
Cancel.
Now we know.
SCOTT:
Captain.
We can do it.
Good.
We have to lay in the automatic
transporter setting,
but when we interrupt
engine circuits
to tie the power increase
into the transporter,
it'll show up
on Sulu's security board.
Of course,
we'll only need a second.
I'll tell Uhura
to create a diversion,
distract Sulu's attention,
at your signal.
We'd better get back
to our posts.
Keep me advised.
Jim.
If we're here,
what do you suppose
our counterparts are doing
back in our universe?
On our Enterprise.
I order you...
let me go!
Traitors!
Spock, get these men off me!
What is this?
What do you think
you're doing, Spock?
You traitorous pig.
I'll hang you up
by your Vulcan ears.
I'll have you all
executed!
I think not.
Your authority on this ship
is extremely limited, Captain.
The four of you will remain here
in the brig and in custody
until I discover how
to return you
to wherever it is you belong.
Has the whole galaxy
gone crazy?
What kind of a uniform is this?
Where's your beard?
What's going on?
Where's my personal guard?
I can answer none
of your questions at this time.
Ha-ha-ha. All right, Spock.
Whatever your game is,
I'll play it.
You want credits,
I'll give them to you.
You'll be a rich man.
A command of your own?
I can swing that too.
Apparently some kind of
transposition has taken place.
I find it...
extremely interesting.
Spock.
What is it
that will buy you?
Power?
Fascinating.
Power, Spock?
I can get that for you!
Captain.
I am pleased that you frustrated
Mr. Chekov's plan.
I should regret your death.
Why?
I do not desire
the captaincy.
I much prefer
my scientific duties.
And I am frankly content
to be a lesser target.
Logical, as always,
Mr. Spock.
Aagh!
Aaaah!
The agony booth
is a most effective means
of discipline.
Aah!
SPOCK:
I presume you've ordered
full duration.
I haven't decided.
Indeed.
His act warrants death.
I said I haven't decided.
That is, of course,
your affair.
Captain, may I inquire
if you intend to persist
in your unusual course
of action
regarding the Halkans?
You heard my orders.
They are, of course,
in contradiction
to standard
Empire procedure.
You cannot ignore
the consequences.
Is that a threat?
I do not threaten, Captain.
I merely state facts.
I have found you
to be an excellent officer.
Our missions together
have been both successful
and profitable.
However, I shall not permit
your aberrations
to jeopardize my position.
Spock...
Do you think we should
destroy the Halkans?
Terror must be maintained
or the Empire is doomed.
It is the logic of history.
Conquest is easy.
Control is not.
We may have bitten off
more than we can chew.
Captain, I do not wish
to find myself opposing you,
but if you continue
on your present course,
this confusing,
inexplicable behavior...
Is my concern, not yours.
You would find me
a formidable enemy.
I'm aware of that, Captain.
I trust that you are aware
of the reverse.
( dramatic music playing )
Orders, sir?
Release Chekov.
Confine him to quarters.
Yes, sir.
That ought to hold him
for about six hours.
I fell asleep.
We had quite a time
in the chem lab
picking up after the storm.
Nothing compared
to your day, I gather.
I heard about Chekov.
He gambled, I won.
Mm-mm. You got lucky.
I'm surprised that you could be
caught off-guard that way.
I was preoccupied.
Ah.
You're still in trouble
with Starfleet Command.
What you've got in mind
this time is beyond me.
You're scheming,
of course.
The Halkans
have something you want,
or...is it all
some clever means
to advance you
to the admiralty?
Kirk.
The cabinet itself?
Further than that,
if I'm successful.
Really?
Well...
you must know
what you're doing.
You always do.
If I'm to be the woman...
...of a Caesar,
can't I know
what you're up to?
( intercom whistles )
Kirk here.
Mr. Spock, Captain.
Yes.
I've received
a private communication
from Starfleet Command.
I am committing a breach
of regulations
by informing you
of its contents.
Yes, Mr. Spock.
I am instructed to wait
until planet dawn
over principal target
to permit you
to carry out our mission.
And...if I don't?
In that event,
I am ordered to kill you
and to proceed
against the Halkans
as the new captain
of the Enterprise.
Captain's log,
stardate...
unknown.
We are trapped in a savage,
parallel universe
from which we must escape
within four hours,
or I will face a death sentence
at Mr. Spock's hands.
Let's drink a toast
to Spock,
the only man aboard
with the decency to warn you,
and he'll die for it.
You'll never find
another man like him.
I don't intend
to kill him.
Are you going to act
against the Halkans
before the deadline?
No, but I'll avoid
killing Spock.
Just get him out of the way,
he and his men.
I'll get out of his way.
Shall I activate
the Tantalus Field?
You'll at least want
to monitor him, won't you?
Yes.
I hate this thing.
It's not that bad.
Of course not.
It made you captain.
How many enemies have you
simply wiped out of existence
by the touch of a button?
50? 100?
Now, I always thought
that was funny--
the great powerful Captain Kirk,
who owes everything
to some unknown alien scientist
and a plundered laboratory.
Well, if you don't
take advantage
of your opportunities...
You don't rise
to the command of a starship.
Or even higher.
That magnificent mind
of his.
But it can't protect him
from this.
I press it and he dies.
Now?
You really mean it.
It doesn't matter.
If Spock fails his order,
he'll be killed anyway.
I'll see to it that
the circumstances of his failure
will clear him.
You're not even afraid
of Starfleet Command.
Can your scheme bring you
that much power so quickly?
And what about me?
How does Marlena fit in?
How does Marlena want
to fit in?
( softly )
Scotty.
Scotty here, sir.
We have to get out of here
within three hours.
Spock has orders to kill me
unless I complete
the military mission.
We've got another
deadline too, sir.
Explain.
The two-way
matter transmission
affected the local field density
between the universes,
and it's increasing.
We've got to move fast.
How fast?
Half-hour at the most.
If we miss?
We couldn't get out of here
in a century.
Now, we're ready
to bridge power
from the engines
to the transporter.
You've got to get down there
and free the board
so we can lock in.
Now, give me about 10 minutes.
I've got to complete
a few more computations.
All right, I'll be in the
transporter room in 10 minutes.
I'll meet you
in the sick bay afterward.
Aye, sir.
Computer?
Ready.
Explain computer activity
in the engineering section.
A security research is
in progress.
Who is conducting
the research?
The captain and Mr. Scott.
What is the nature
of the research?
Program is classified
under voice index log.
( beeping )
Why are you monitoring
my communications, Mr. Sulu?
My security boards detected
extensive use of computer,
Mr. Spock.
I was about to inform you.
It's not hard to guess
the nature of your order
from Starfleet Command.
I suggest a...connection.
The captain suspects.
He's working on escape
or defense.
That is my concern.
Correct. It's your play.
I hope you succeed,
because the order
would fall on me next,
and you know how
Captain Kirk's enemies
have a habit of...
disappearing.
If I am successful,
you see yourself a step nearer
to the captaincy.
I do not want to command
the Enterprise,
but if it should befall me,
I suggest you remember
that my operatives
would avenge my death,
and some of them...
are Vulcans.
Oiling my traps,
darling.
I'm afraid I'm a little
out of practice.
Maybe that's what happened
to us, hm?
It's very hard
for a working officer
to shine as a woman
every minute...
and you demand perfection.
I've never seen perfection,
but no woman
could come closer to it.
I remember when you
used to talk that way.
I still do.
Prove it.
I've got to go.
Ship's business?
An important task
on the crew deck?
Well...
I guess it's over.
Commander Kenno
will take me temporarily.
He has made that quite clear.
I'll call a yeoman
to help me with my things.
You don't have to do that.
Are you feeling sorry
for me?
Do I see hesitation
in your eyes...
about anything?
I want one thing,
Captain.
Transfer me.
On the Enterprise,
I am humiliated.
On another ship,
I can hunt fresh game.
I've got my rank, and--
Don't I?
I've been a captain's woman,
and I like it.
I'll be one again
if I have to go through
every officer in the fleet.
You could.
I simply meant...
that you could be anything
you want to be.
It's...been a long time
since you've...
kissed me like that.
You're a stranger.
Mercy to the Halkans.
Mercy to Spock...
to me.
Am I your woman?
You're the captain's woman
until he says you're not.
Uhura.
Yes, Captain.
Scotty's signal should be coming
through any moment now.
You know what to do.
I've got
a pretty good idea, sir.
Keep Sulu's attention
off that board.
I'll do my best, sir.
Good luck. Kirk out.
( beeps )
You aren't
very persistent, Mr. Sulu.
The game has rules.
You're ignoring them.
I protest,
and you come back.
You didn't come back.
Now you're making sense.
I was... getting bored.
Mm-hm?
Of course
this isn't the time.
Any time's a good time.
I'm afraid
I changed my mind... again.
You take a lot of chances,
Lieutenant.
So do you, mister.
So do you.
Take over for me.
Mr. Scott, all clear.
On my way to Sick Bay.
Now it's up to
the captain.
You'll please restrict
your movements, Captain.
What are you doing?
Are you gonna
shoot me now, Spock?
I thought I had until dawn.
I shall make that decision.
Since your return
from the planet,
you've behaved in a most
atypical and illogical manner.
I want to know why.
Shoot.
You're wasting time.
I shall not waste time
with you.
You're too inflexible,
too disciplined
once you've made up
your mind.
But Dr. McCoy has a plenitude
of human weaknesses--
sentimental, soft.
You may not tell me
what I want to know,
but he will.
You're running
a big risk, Spock.
I have the phaser, Captain,
and I do not intend
to simply disappear
as so many of your opponents
have in the past.
If you please...
Sick Bay.
( dramatic music playing )
Yes, of course.
The entire landing party.
Captain, stand over there.
Doctor, it is time
for answers.
How much time, Scotty?
Hardly 15 minutes, sir.
The field density
between the two universes
is starting to close
very fast.
Help me get him
on the table.
Well, come on.
Help me get him on the table.
He'll die
without immediate treatment.
Everything laid in,
Scotty--
the time lag
so the operator can get
into the transporter chamber?
All laid in, sir.
Come on, McCoy.
We're taking a chance
of not getting back home.
We'll get home.
This won't take long.
SCOTT:
14 minutes.
We've got to go!
Will you shut up?
I can save his life.
Do you want me to stop, Jim?
It'll only take a minute.
He is very much like
our own Mr. Spock, isn't he?
You've got that minute.
DR. McCOY:
A little time, he'll live.
What is this,
Mr. Sulu?
Mr. Spock has orders
to kill you, Captain.
He will succeed...
apparently.
You will also appear
to have killed him...
after a fierce battle.
Regrettable,
but it will leave me
in command.
( dramatic music playing )
Oh!
Captain, we've barely got
10 minutes!
Let's go, Bones.
I can't let him die, Jim.
Look, you get down
to the transporter room.
Make sure it's clear.
I'll be there in five minutes.
No longer.
I guarantee it.
Now go on, please.
Why did the captain
let me live?
Our minds are merging,
Doctor.
Our minds are one.
I feel what you feel.
I know what you know.
A friend.
Activate the transporter.
You saved us
back at Sick Bay
with the Tantalus Field.
Take me with you.
I can't.
I'm sorry.
Our power is balanced for four.
There's no guarantee
that we'll make it with five.
All could die.
Scotty?
It's working, sir.
But there are
only three of you.
One is coming.
I'd help you
if I could, Marlena.
Believe that.
If you kill us,
you'll still stay.
Where's McCoy?
Time, Scotty?
Five minutes, sir.
Do you know
what they'll do to me?
The power's cut, sir.
They're on to us!
Auxiliary.
It's available.
Can you bridge
to your setup?
Oh, I can get us the power,
but the automatic setting
is linked
to the transporter main.
If we bypass,
that means that someone
has got to operate
the controls manually.
One of us will have to stay.
I'll stay, Captain.
Get to the transporter chamber.
You, too, Uhura.
Jim!
That's an order,
Scotty.
Aye, Captain.
What about me?
( mutters )
McCoy.
I cut the transporter power.
It was necessary
to delay your beam out
until I could arrive.
Take him.
Engineering, reactivate
main transporter circuits.
You're a man of integrity
in both universes, Mr. Spock.
You must return
to your universe.
I must have my captain back.
I shall operate
the transporter.
You have 2 minutes
and 10 seconds.
With that time,
I have something to say.
How long
before the Halkan prediction
of galactic revolt
is realized?
Approximately 240 years.
The inevitable outcome?
The Empire shall be overthrown,
of course.
The illogic of waste,
Mr. Spock,
the waste of lives,
potential, resources, time.
I submit to you
that your empire is illogical
because it cannot endure.
I submit
that you are illogical
to be a willing part
of it.
You have one minute
and 23 seconds.
If change is inevitable,
predictable, beneficial,
doesn't logic demand
that you be a part of it?
One man
cannot summon the future.
But one man can change
the present.
Be the captain of this
Enterprise, Mr. Spock.
Find a logical reason
for sparing the Halkans.
And make it stick.
Push till it gives.
You can defend yourself
better than any man
in the fleet.
Captain,
get in the chamber!
What about it, Spock?
A man must also have the power.
In my cabin
is a device that will
make you invincible.
Indeed?
What will it be?
Past or future?
Tyranny or freedom?
It's up to you.
It is time.
In every revolution,
there's one man with a vision.
Captain Kirk,
I shall consider it.
Spock.
Welcome home,
Captain.
What I don't understand
is how you were able
to identify our counterparts
so quickly.
It was far easier
for you, as civilized men,
to behave like barbarians
than it was for them,
as barbarians,
to behave
like civilized men.
I assume they returned
to their Enterprise
at the same time
you appeared here?
Probably.
However, that Jim Kirk
will find a few changes,
if I read my Spocks correctly.
Jim, I think I liked him
with a beard better.
It gave him character.
Of course,
almost any change
would be
a distinct improvement.
What worries me is the easy way
his counterpart fitted
into that other universe.
I always thought Spock
was a bit of a pirate at heart.
Indeed, gentlemen.
May I point out
that I had an opportunity
to observe your counterparts
here quite closely.
They were brutal, savage,
unprincipled,
uncivilized, treacherous,
in every way, splendid examples
of Homo sapiens,
the very flower of humanity.
I found them quite refreshing.
I'm not sure, but I think
we've been insulted.
I'm sure.
Captain Kirk.
Lieutenant,
uh, Lieutenant...?
Marlena Moreau.
I was just assigned
last week.
All right, Lieutenant.
Carry on.
You've met her before,
Captain?
Uh, why do you ask?
Your reaction.
One of... recognition?
Oh, no. No, no.
We-we haven't met
before...
exactly.
She just seemed...
a nice, likable girl.
I-I think
we could become friends.
It's possible.
( main theme playing )