START YOUR READINGS.
WELL...
I JUST MIGHT
STAKE OUT A CLAIM
AND SETTLE DOWN
HERE, JIM.
IT IS SPECTACULAR,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S A SHAME
TO INTRUDE.
WELL, THE LAST SCOUT SHIP
REPORTED SOME PRETTY
STRANGE SENSOR READINGS.
STARFLEET WANTS
IT INVESTIGATED
AND THE INHABITANTS
CONTACTED.
WE DO WHAT WE'RE TOLD.
THE SOIL HERE IS
REMARKABLY RICH AND
FERTILE, CAPTAIN.
HUSBANDRY WOULD BE
QUITE EFFICACIOUS.
YOU SURE ABOUT THAT?
OH, QUITE SURE.
READINGS INDICATE
THE ENTIRE PLANET
IS COVERED WITH
GROWTH LIKE THIS.
CURIOUS--
EVEN AT THE POLES
THERE'S VERY
LITTLE VARIATION
IN TEMPERATURE
WHICH MAINTAINS
A PLANETWIDE AVERAGE
OF 76 DEGREES.
I KNOW.
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE.
IT MAKES ME HOMESICK.
JUST LIKE RUSSIA.
MORE LIKE THE GARDEN
OF EDEN, ENSIGN.
OF COURSE, DOCTOR.
THE GARDEN
OF EDEN WAS JUST
OUTSIDE MOSCOW.
A VERY NICE PLACE.
IT MUST'VE MADE
ADAM AND EVE
VERY SAD TO LEAVE.
"JUST OUTSIDE MOSCOW."
ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S A VILLAGE ABOUT
17 KILOMETERS AWAY
ON BEARING 2-3-2.
WE'LL HEAD THAT WAY.
CAPTAIN.
Captain.
DEAD.
WHAT DID SOMEBODY SAY?
THAT PARADISE MUST'VE
LOOKED LIKE THIS?
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3715.3.
WHILE MAKING
A ROUTINE EXPLORATION
OF THE UNEXPLORED
GAMMA TRIANGULI 6,
ONE OF MY MEN HAS BEEN KILLED
BY A POISONOUS PLANT.
AS SOON AS WE GET
OUT OF THE WAY,
BEAM THE BODY UP.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S A SHAME
ABOUT HENDORFF.
WE SEEM TO HAVE
A PROBLEM HERE, TOO.
WHAT IS IT?
WE'RE LOSING POTENCY
IN OUR ANTIMATTER PODS.
I DON'T THINK
IT'S SERIOUS,
BUT WE'RE LOOKING INTO IT.
WHAT'S CAUSING IT?
I'M NOT SURE, SIR.
BUT WE'VE RUN MEASUREMENTS
ON THE ELECTROMAGNETIC
FIELD OF THE PLANET,
AND THEY ARE
A WEE BIT ABNORMAL.
THAT MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING
TO DO WITH IT.
BUT YOU SAY
THERE'S NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT?
WELL, SIR, I DIDN'T
EXACTLY SAY THAT.
WELL, STAY
ON TOP OF IT.
WE'VE GOT A JOB
TO DO HERE. WE MIGHT
AS WELL FINISH IT.
I HEAR
IT'S NICE DOWN THERE.
YEAH.
IT'S NICE.
IF WE'RE A LITTLE
MORE CAREFUL,
WE SHOULDN'T RUN
INTO ANY MORE TROUBLE.
I COULD DO WITH A NICE
WALK IN A GARDEN
WITH GREEN LEAVES
AND GRASS.
WE'LL DO
THE WALKING, SCOTTY.
YOU GET ON
THE ANTIMATTER POD.
IF IT GETS ANY WORSE,
LET ME KNOW, WE'LL BEAM UP.
KIRK OUT.
I FIND THAT MOST
UNUSUAL, CAPTAIN.
WELL, SCOTTY
WILL HANDLE IT.
WE GOT A JOB TO DO.
TURN UP ANYTHING
ON YOUR TRICORDER?
INDEED. SUBSURFACE
VIBRATIONS FOR MILES
IN ALL DIRECTIONS.
THAT'S STRANGE.
QUITE STRONG,
FAIRLY REGULAR,
ARTIFICIALLY PRODUCED.
MALLORY.
YES, CAPTAIN?
WE'RE HEADING
FOR THE VILLAGE.
AVOID CONTACT
WITH THE HUMANOIDS.
AND I WANT YOU
AND MARPLE TO MAKE
A FULL RECONNAISSANCE.
SO BE CAREFUL. THERE
MAY BE OTHER DANGERS
BESIDES POISONOUS PLANTS.
KEEP IN CONSTANT
COMMUNICATION.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S A HUMANOID HIDING
DIRECTLY BEHIND US
MOVING WITH
REMARKABLE AGILITY,
BEARING 1-8.
WHAT IS IT,
MR. SPOCK?
A VISITOR.
ONE WANTING TO RETAIN HIS
ANONYMITY, I SHOULD SAY.
ALL THIS BEAUTY,
AND NOW MR. HENDORFF DEAD,
SOMEBODY WATCHING US.
IT'S FRIGHTENING.
IF YOU INSIST
ON WORRYING,
WORRY ABOUT ME.
I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO GET YOU IN
A PLACE LIKE THIS
FOR A LONG TIME.
MR. CHEKOV,
LIEUTENANT LANDON.
I KNOW YOU FIND EACH
OTHER FASCINATING,
BUT WE'RE NOT HERE
TO CONDUCT
A FIELD EXPERIMENT
IN HUMAN BIOLOGY.
I WAS JUST ABOUT
TO TAKE SOME READINGS.
ANYTHING?
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT MOVES LIKE A CAT.
JIM, I DON'T LIKE THIS.
NEITHER DO I.
ALL HANDS!
WE'VE BEEN WATCHED,
WE'LL PROBABLY
BE WATCHED.
WE'RE MOVING OUT.
FORMATION "L."
INTERESTING.
EXTREMELY LOW
SPECIFIC GRAVITY,
SOME URANINITE,
HORNLBLENDE,
QUARTZ.
FRAGILE,
GOOD CLEAVAGE.
AN ANALYSIS SHOULD
PROVE INTERESTING.
WOULD YOU MIND
BEING CAREFUL WHERE YOU
THROW YOUR ROCKS, MR. SPOCK?
OBVIOUSLY HIGHLY
UNSTABLE, CAPTAIN.
THIS COULD BE A FIND
OF SOME IMPORTANCE.
IN LARGE QUANTITIES,
IT COULD BE
A CONSIDERABLE
SOURCE OF POWER.
GARDEN OF EDEN...
WITH LAND MINES.
"ENTERPRISE"
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
SCOTT, SIR.
OUR ANTIMATTER PODS
ARE COMPLETELY INERT.
I COULDN'T STOP IT,
BUT I KNOW WHY.
WHY?
SOMETHING FROM THE SURFACE.
IT'S LIKE A PAIL
OF WATER ON A FIRE.
A BEAM, MAYBE,
OR A TRANSMISSION.
AND IT'S STILL ON.
I'M HAVING IT ANALYZED,
BUT IT'S LIKE NOTHING
I'VE EVER SEEN BEFORE.
AND IT'S PINPOINTED
IN THE AREA OF THAT VILLAGE
WE LOCATED DOWN THERE.
WE'RE HEADING
THERE NOW, SCOTTY.
NEED ANY HELP?
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING YOU
CAN DO ABOUT IT, SIR.
AND THERE DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
ANY IMMEDIATE DANGER.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
WE'LL TRY AND FIND OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON DOWN HERE.
KIRK OUT.
IF SCOTT IS CORRECT
ABOUT THE FORCE
FROM THE SURFACE,
IT MAY HAVE TO DO
WITH THE VIBRATIONS
I READ EARLIER.
SOME KIND OF GENERATOR?
IF SO,
AN IMMENSE ONE,
PROBABLY
SUBTERRANEAN.
WHAT'S THAT?
SOME OF THE THORNS LIKE
THOSE THAT KILLED HENDORFF.
SEE THE STUFF
ON THE END?
IT'S LIKE SAPLIN, ONLY
IT'S 1,000 TIMES STRONGER
PECULIAR STUFF
TO FIND IN PARADISE.
JIM!
SPOCK!
SECURITY ALERT.
IS HE ALIVE?
[HYPOSPRAY HISSES]
I FILLED HIM WITH
ENOUGH MASSOFORM "D"
TO MAKE
THE WHOLE CREW
TURN HANDSPRINGS
AND HE'S NOT
RESPONDING.
WE'VE GOT
TO GET HIM BACK
TO THE SHIP, JIM.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
WE'RE BEAMING UP.
NOTIFY TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AND MAKE ARRANGEMENTS TO
PICK UP MALLORY AND MARPLE.
THEY'RE SCOUTING
AHEAD OF US.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
TRANSPORTER ROOM, STAND BY
TO BEAM UP LANDING PARTY.
ALL HANDS!
STANDING BY, SIR.
ENERGIZE.
SCOTTY, ENERGIZE.
SCOTTY,
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WE CAN'T MAKE
TRANSPORTER CONTACT, SIR.
THE ENTIRE SYSTEM'S
INHIBITED.
THE WAY IT IS NOW,
WE COULDN'T
BEAM UP A FLY.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTARY--
OUR INVESTIGATION
OF GAMMA TRIANGULI 6
HAS SUDDENLY TURNED
INTO A NIGHTMARE.
WE'RE BEING WATCHED
AND FOLLOWED,
MR. SPOCK
HAS BEEN INJURED,
AND NOW WE FIND
WE ARE UNABLE TO
RETURN TO THE SHIP.
SCOTTY, IS
THE TRANSPORTER
MALFUNCTION
TIED IN WITH
THE TROUBLE
YOU'RE HAVING
WITH THE ANTIMATTER
PODS?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
I'LL CHECK IT
AND GET BACK TO
YOU. SCOTT OUT.
SPOCK.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
DR. McCOY'S POTION
IS ACTING LIKE
ALL HIS POTIONS--
TURNING MY STOMACH.
OTHER THAN THAT,
I AM QUITE WELL.
WELL, IF YOUR
BLOOD WERE RED
INSTEAD OF GREEN,
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
AN UPSET STOMACH.
JUST WHAT DID YOU THINK
YOU WERE TRYING TO DO?
I SURMISED YOU WERE
UNAWARE OF THAT
PLANT, SO I--
STEPPED IN FRONT AND
TOOK THE THORNS YOURSELF.
I ASSURE YOU,
CAPTAIN,
I HAD NO INTENTION
OF DOING THAT.
IT WAS MERELY
MY OWN CLUMSINESS
WHICH PREVENTED ME
FROM MOVING
OUT OF THE WAY.
I SEE. WELL, NEXT TIME,
JUST YELL. I CAN
STEP OUT OF THE WAY
AS QUICKLY
AS THE NEXT MAN.
I SHALL DO SO.
TRYING TO GET
YOURSELF KILLED.
YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH STARFLEET
HAS INVESTED IN YOU?
122,22--
NEVER MIND.
BUT...
THANKS.
KAPLAN,
TAKE THE POST.
YES, SIR.
NOT ONLY IS
SOMETHING AFTER US,
BUT IT'S AFTER
THE SHIP AS WELL.
CAPTAIN, TO AFFECT THE SHIP
AT THIS EXTREME RANGE
WOULD REQUIRE
A HIGHLY SOPHISTICATED
PLANETARY DEFENSE SYSTEM.
30 SECONDS AGO,
THERE WASN'T A CLOUD
IN THE SKY.
COVER!
PHASERS.
BEAUTIFUL DAY,
MR. SPOCK.
NOT A CLOUD IN THE SKY.
JUST LIKE PARADISE.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
MALLORY HERE, CAPTAIN.
I'M NEAR THE VILLAGE.
COORDINATES--
1-1-8 BY 2-2-0.
[STATIC]
MALLORY.
MALLORY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
COME IN!
THE VILLAGE IS...
PRIMITIVE.
STRICTLY TRIBAL
FROM THE LOOKS OF IT.
AND, CAPTAIN, THERE'S
SOMETHING ELSE.
[STATIC]
CAPTAIN, COME IN!
MALLORY.
MALLORY, YOU ALL RIGHT?
MALLORY!
CAPTAIN.
THOSE COORDINATES
ARE A SHORT DISTANCE
IN THAT DIRECTION.
ON THE DOUBLE.
IT'S OVER THERE!
THAT WAY! I NEVER SAW
ANYTHING LIKE--
MALLORY!
MARPLE, STAND BACK!
WATCH IT!
ROCKS!
KAPLAN.
HENDORFF.
I KNEW
KAPLAN'S FAMILY.
NOW MALLORY.
JIM, YOU COULDN'T HAVE
STOPPED ANY OF THIS.
HIS FATHER
HELPED ME GET
INTO THE ACADEMY.
CAPTAIN.
IN EACH CASE,
THIS WAS UNAVOIDABLE.
I COULD'VE PREVENTED
ALL OF IT.
I DON'T SEE HOW.
WALK IN PARADISE...
AMONG
THE GREEN GRASS
AND THE FLOWERS.
I SHOULD'VE BEAMED
UP AT THE FIRST
SIGN OF TROUBLE.
YOU ARE UNDER ORDERS
TO INVESTIGATE THIS
PLANET AND THIS CULTURE.
I ALSO HAVE THE OPTION
TO DISREGARD THOSE
ORDERS IF I CONSIDER
THEM OVERLY HAZARDOUS.
THIS ISN'T
THAT IMPORTANT
A MISSION, SPOCK.
NOT WORTH THE LIVES
OF THREE OF MY MEN.
I DROP MY GUARD
FOR A MINUTE
BECAUSE
I LIKE THE SMELL
OF GROWING THINGS,
AND NOW
THREE MEN ARE DEAD.
AND THE SHIP'S
IN TROUBLE.
NO ONE HAS EVER STATED
THAT STARFLEET DUTY
WAS PARTICULARLY SAFE.
YOU'VE FOLLOWED THE CORRECT
AND LOGICAL COURSE,
DONE EVERYTHING
A COMMANDER COULD DO.
SELF-RECRIMINATIONS...
CAPTAIN...
OUR FRIEND IS BACK.
[LEAVES RUSTLE]
MARPLE, CHEKOV,
AT ATTENTION.
GENTLEMEN,
SOMETHING OR SOMEONE
IS BEHIND THAT ROCK.
I WANT IT.
MARPLE,
CUT AROUND THE ROCK
TO YOUR RIGHT.
MAKE A LOUD NOISE.
BE CAREFUL.
SPOCK...
YOU AND CHEKOV
CREATE A DIVERSION
AND MAKE IT LOUD.
MR. CHEKOV, YOUR
TRICORDER READINGS ARE
TOTALLY INEFFICIENT!
MIND YOUR OWN
BUSINESS!
FOR YOUR INFORMATION,
I HAVE A VERY HIGH
EFFICIENCY RATING!
ENSIGN, I WILL NOT
HAVE YOU ADDRESS ME
IN THAT TONE OF VOICE!
WHAT DO YOU WANT,
VIOLINS?
[CRYING]
I WON'T HURT YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU STRUCK ME.
WITH YOUR HAND.
WELL, I WON'T
STRIKE YOU AGAIN.
YOU'VE BEEN
FOLLOWING US...
WATCHING US. WHY?
I AM THE EYES OF VAAL.
HE MUST SEE.
WHO IS VAAL?
VAAL IS VAAL.
HE IS...
EVERYTHING.
DO YOU HAVE A NAME?
I AM AKUTA.
I AM THE LEADER OF
THE FEEDERS OF VAAL.
THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO HURT YOU.
I PROMISE YOU.
AKUTA...
WE COME IN PEACE.
WE WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK
TO THIS VAAL.
AKUTA ALONE
SPEAKS TO VAAL.
I AM THE EYES AND
THE VOICE OF VAAL.
IT IS VAAL'S WISH.
CAPTAIN,
THIS IS FASCINATING.
IF YOU WILL
PERMIT ME, SIR?
ANTENNAE?
THEY ARE MY
EARS FOR VAAL.
THEY WERE
GIVEN TO ME
IN THE DIM TIME
SO THE PEOPLE
COULD UNDERSTAND
HIS COMMANDS
AND OBEY.
YOU SPEAK OF THE PEOPLE
OF VAAL. ARE THEY NEARBY?
WE ARE CLOSE TO VAAL
SO WE MAY SERVE HIM.
I SHALL
TAKE YOU THERE.
"ENTERPRISE"
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
CONDITION RED!
CAPTAIN...
SOMETHING HAS
GRABBED US FROM THE
PLANET'S SURFACE,
LIKE A GIANT
TRACTOR BEAM AND WE
CAN'T BREAK LOOSE.
IT'S NO USE, MR. SCOTT.
WE'RE JUST BARELY
HOLDING OUR OWN.
SCOTTY, IS THE WARP
DRIVE STILL OUT?
AYE, SIR.
ALL WE HAVE
IS IMPULSE POWER.
PUT IT ON MAXIMUM.
FULL EMERGENCY CIRCUITS.
THEY'RE ALL ON,
CAPTAIN.
STATUS--ARE YOU
STILL HOLDING?
KYLE.
NO, SIR.
WE'RE SLIPPING.
COMPUTER BANKS,
KYLE.
FEED IN OUR RATE.
GET ME A FIGURE.
WE MIGHT BE
ABLE TO PULL OUT
WITH WARP DRIVE.
BUT WITHOUT IT,
WE'RE LIKE A FLY
ON FLYPAPER.
EVEN WORSE,
WE'RE STARTING
TO LOSE GROUND.
HURRY UP WITH
THAT FIGURE, KYLE.
MAINTAIN FULL REVERSE THRUST
AGAINST THE PULL.
PUT A TEAM ON
THAT WARP DRIVE.
GET IT WORKING.
I'VE DONE THAT,
CAPTAIN.
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN
ABLE TO DO A THING.
IT'S NO GOOD, CAPTAIN.
WITH MAXIMUM THRUST
AGAINST THE PULL,
WE'LL ONLY BE ABLE
TO MAINTAIN FULL POWER
FOR 16 HOURS,
THEN WE BURN UP FOR SURE.
SCOTTY...
YOU'RE MY CHIEF ENGINEER.
YOU KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT THAT SHIP THAT
THERE IS TO KNOW,
MORE THAN THE MEN
WHO DESIGNED IT.
IF YOU CAN'T GET THOSE
WARP ENGINES WORKING...
YOU'RE FIRED.
I'LL DO EVERYTHING
THERE IS TO DO, SIR.
SCOTT OUT.
TELL ME ABOUT VAAL.
ALL THE WORLD
KNOWS ABOUT VAAL.
HE CAUSES THE RAINS
TO FALL AND THE SUN
TO SHINE.
ALL GOOD
COMES FROM VAAL.
TAKE ME TO HIM.
I WISH TO SPEAK TO HIM.
I SHALL
TAKE YOU TO HIM,
BUT HE WILL
NOT SPEAK TO YOU. HE
SPEAKS ONLY TO ME.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES.
VAAL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3715.6.
WE HAVE BEEN
INTRODUCED TO VAAL.
EVIDENTLY THE SOURCE
OF THE PLANET'S
POWER EMANATIONS
AND POSSIBLY THE FORCE
THAT THREATENS BOTH US
AND OUR SHIP.
FASCINATING.
VERY HIGH
ORDER OF WORKMANSHIP.
VERY ANCIENT.
GENERATING GREAT POWER.
BUT THIS IS NOT THE
CENTER, MR. SPOCK?
NO, CAPTAIN. THE CENTER IS
DEEP IN THE EARTH BENEATH US.
THIS IS AN ACCESS POINT.
IT WOULD
ALSO SEEM TO BE--
A FORCE FIELD?
OBVIOUSLY.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, QUITE.
IT EXTENDS SOME
30 FEET BEYOND THE FIGURE
IN ALL DIRECTIONS.
CONVENTIONAL
IN COMPOSITION...
AND QUITE FORMIDABLE.
AKUTA, HOW DO YOU
TALK TO VAAL?
VAAL CALLS ME.
ONLY THEN.
WELL, WE CAN'T GET TO IT.
WE CAN'T TALK TO IT
UNLESS IT WANTS
TO TALK TO US.
VAAL SLEEPS NOW.
WHEN HE IS HUNGRY,
YOU MAY BE ABLE
TO SPEAK WITH HIM
IF HE DESIRES IT.
WHEN DOES HE GET HUNGRY?
SOON.
COME. WE WILL GIVE YOU
FOOD AND DRINK.
IF YOU ARE TIRED,
YOU MAY REST.
THESE ARE
PEOPLE OF VAAL.
WHERE ARE THE OTHERS?
THERE ARE NO OTHERS.
THE, UH, CHILDREN.
CHILDREN?
HA HA. YOU USE
UNKNOWN WORDS TO ME.
LITTLE ONES
LIKE YOURSELVES.
THEY GROW.
AHH! REPLACEMENTS.
NONE ARE NECESSARY.
THEY ARE FORBIDDEN
BY VAAL.
BUT WHEN A MAN
AND WOMAN FALL IN LOVE...
"LOVE."
HA HA HA HA.
STRANGE WORDS--
CHILDREN, LOVE.
WHAT IS LOVE?
LOVE IS...
WHEN TWO PEOPLE ARE...
AHH...
YES. THE HOLDING.
THE TOUCHING.
VAAL HAS FORBIDDEN THIS.
WELL, THERE GOES
PARADISE.
THESE PEOPLE...
ARE FROM ANOTHER PLACE.
THEY HAVE COME AMONG US.
WELCOME THEM!
WELCOME TO VAAL.
OUR HOMES
ARE OPEN TO YOU.
WELL, THANK YOU.
IT, UH,
DOES SOMETHING FOR YOU.
YES, INDEED
IT DOES, CAPTAIN.
IT MAKES ME
UNCOMFORTABLE.
I AM SAYANA.
YOU HAVE A NAME?
YES. SPOCK.
I AM SPOCK.
HA HA HA.
SPOCK?
I FAIL TO SEE
WHAT THEY FIND
SO AMUSING.
HA HA HA HA!
HA HA...
COME!
THIS HOUSE IS YOUR HOUSE.
I WILL SEND YOU
MORE FOOD AND DRINK.
YOU ARE WELCOME
IN THE PLACE OF VAAL.
NOW WE'RE WELCOME.
A WHILE AGO,
THIS WHOLE PLANET
WAS TRYING TO KILL US.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
NOTHING MAKES
SENSE DOWN HERE. KIRK
TO "ENTERPRISE." COME IN.
SCOTT HERE.
STATUS REPORT, SCOTTY.
NO CHANGE, CAPTAIN.
THE ORBIT IS DECAYING
ALONG COMPUTED LINES.
NO SUCCESS WITH
THE WARP DRIVE.
WE'RE GOING DOWN,
AND WE CAN'T STOP IT.
I'M SICK OF HEARING
THAT WORD "CAN'T." GET
THAT SHIP OUT OF THERE!
SIR, WE'RE DOING
EVERYTHING WITHIN
ENGINEERING REASON.
THEN USE
YOUR IMAGINATION.
TIE EVERY OUNCE OF
POWER THE SHIP HAS
INTO THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
DISCARD THE WARP DRIVE
AND NACELLES
IF YOU HAVE TO
AND CRACK OUT OF THERE
WITH THE MAIN SECTION,
BUT GET THAT SHIP
OUT OF THERE!
SIR, I'M GOING TO
SWITCH OVER EVERYTHING
BUT THE LIFE SUPPORT
SYSTEMS AND BOOST
THE IMPULSE POWER,
BUT THAT'S JUST
ABOUT AS DANGEROUS.
DO IT. KIRK OUT.
INCREDIBLE.
REPORT.
I JUST RAN A THOROUGH
CHECK ON THE NATIVES,
AND THERE'S
A COMPLETE LACK
OF HARMFUL BACTERIA
IN THEIR SYSTEMS,
NO DECALCIFICATION,
NO DEGENERATION
OF TISSUE,
NO ARTERIOSCLEROSIS.
IN SIMPLE TERMS, JIM...
THEY'RE NOT GROWING OLD,
AND I CAN'T BEGIN TO TELL
YOU HOW OLD THEY ARE--
20 YEARS OR 20,000 YEARS.
I SEE.
OPINION.
QUITE POSSIBLE.
IT CHECKS WITH
MY ATMOSPHERIC ANALYSIS.
THEIR ATMOSPHERE
COMPLETELY NEGATES
ANY HARMFUL EFFECTS
FROM THEIR SUN.
ADD TO THAT
A SIMPLE DIET...
PERFECTLY CONTROLLED
TEMPERATURE...
NO NATURAL ENEMIES...
APPARENTLY NO VICES,
NO REPLACEMENTS NEEDED.
MAYBE IT IS PARADISE
AFTER ALL.
[GONG SOUNDS]
MR. SPOCK.
APPARENTLY,
OUR HYPOTHESIS
IS CORRECT.
THERE IS
NO LIVING BEING THERE.
IT IS A MACHINE,
NOTHING MORE.
WELL, THE FIELD'S DOWN,
PEOPLE ARE GOING IN.
LET'S SEE WHAT KIND
OF LUCK WE HAVE.
[THUNDER]
THAT'S NOT THE WAY.
EVIDENTLY NOT.
THIS IS NO ORDINARY
MACHINE, CAPTAIN.
IT MAY WELL POSSESS
A RUDIMENTARY INTELLIGENCE.
BUT IT NEEDS
TO EAT FREQUENTLY,
SO IT CAN'T HAVE ANY
GREAT POWER RESERVES.
THAT MAY NOT BE
OF ANY HELP.
THE "ENTERPRISE" HAS
ONLY 10 HOURS LEFT
IN WHICH TO BREAK FREE.
YEAH.
WHAT HAPPENS...
IF VAAL WEAKENS
AROUND FEEDING TIME?
SPOCK, CHECK THE
ELECTROMAGNETIC SECTION
OF THE ASTROPHYSICS LAB.
GET AN ESTIMATE
OF THE TOTAL AMOUNT
OF ENERGY
BEING EXPENDED
AGAINST THE SHIP.
HAVE THEM MEASURE IT
HOUR BY HOUR.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
WHAT'S GOING ON, JIM?
MESS CALL.
IN MY VIEW,
A SPLENDID EXAMPLE
OF RECIPROCITY.
IT WOULD TAKE
A COMPUTERIZED VULCAN
MIND, SUCH AS YOURS,
TO MAKE THAT KIND
OF A STATEMENT.
DOCTOR, YOU INSIST ON
APPLYING HUMAN STANDARDS
TO NONHUMAN CULTURES.
I REMIND YOU THAT HUMANS
ARE ONLY A TINY MINORITY
IN THIS GALAXY.
THERE ARE
CERTAIN ABSOLUTES,
MR. SPOCK.
AND ONE OF THEM IS
THE RIGHT OF HUMANOIDS
TO A FREE AND
UNCHAINED ENVIRONMENT,
THE RIGHT
TO HAVE CONDITIONS
WHICH PERMIT GROWTH.
ANOTHER IS THEIR RIGHT
TO CHOOSE A SYSTEM
WHICH SEEMS
TO WORK FOR THEM.
JIM, YOU'RE NOT JUST
GOING TO STAND BY
AND BE BLINDED
TO WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
THESE ARE HUMANOIDS,
INTELLIGENT.
THEY NEED
TO ADVANCE AND GROW.
DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND WHAT
MY READINGS INDICATE?
THERE'S BEEN NO CHANGE
OR PROGRESS HERE IN
AT LEAST 10,000 YEARS.
THIS ISN'T LIFE.
IT'S STAGNATION.
DOCTOR, THESE PEOPLE
ARE HEALTHY
AND THEY ARE HAPPY.
WHATEVER YOU CHOOSE
TO CALL IT,
THIS SYSTEM WORKS,
DESPITE YOUR EMOTIONAL
REACTION TO IT.
IT MIGHT WORK FOR
YOU, MR. SPOCK,
BUT IT DOESN'T
WORK FOR ME.
HUMANOIDS...LIVING
SO THEY CAN SERVICE
A HUNK OF TIN.
GENTLEMEN, I THINK
THIS PHILOSOPHICAL
ARGUMENT CAN WAIT
UNTIL OUR SHIP
IS OUT OF DANGER.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
SCOTTY, SIR.
WE HAVE A READING
ON THE POWER SOURCE
MR. SPOCK REQUESTED.
WHEN WE FIRST MONITORED,
IT WAS GENERATING
ALTERNATING CYCLES
TOTALLING 100
TO THE 20th POWER
WALTHAM UNITS.
DID IT MAINTAIN, SCOTTY?
NO, SIR.
POWER'S DROPPING
BIT BY BIT,
NOMINAL
BUT A DEFINITE DRAIN.
GOOD. KEEP MONITORING.
HOW ARE YOU
COMING ALONG WITH
THE CIRCUIT SWITCHOVER?
WE'RE PUTTING EVERYTHING
BUT THE KITCHEN SINK
INTO THE IMPULSE POWER, SIR.
IT WILL TAKE US
ANOTHER EIGHT HOURS
TO COMPLETE THE WORK.
THAT'S CUTTING IT
A BIT FINE, SCOTTY.
AYE, BUT IF WE
DON'T BREAK OUT...
I'D RATHER WE DIDN'T
HAVE TO WAIT TOO LONG
FOR THE END OF IT.
KIRK OUT.
EVERY TIME I THINK
OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
BURNING UP AND US--
YEOMAN, YOU'RE
WASTING ENERGY.
CAPTAIN,
WE ARE TRAPPED ON THIS--
SIT DOWN...
AND HAVE
SOMETHING TO EAT.
THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS UP THERE--
THAT HASN'T
HAPPENED YET.
I WONDER WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN...
YEOMAN, SPECULATE.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF SOMEONE
ON THIS PLANET DIED?
BUT THEY CAN'T.
YOU SAID THAT VAAL
TAKES CARE OF THEM.
ACCIDENTS HAPPEN.
YES...I SUPPOSE
IF SOMEONE
WERE TO FALL OFF
A CLIFF OR SOMETHING,
THAT MIGHT
UPSET THE BALANCE
OF THE POPULATION.
THEN THEY WOULD
NEED A REPLACEMENT.
THEY'D NEED
A REPLACEMENT.
OPINION, MR. SPOCK?
I SEE
NO ALTERNATIVE.
BUT THESE PEOPLE...
I MEAN, IF THEY DON'T
KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT...
WHAT I MEAN IS...
THEY DON'T SEEM
TO HAVE ANY NATURAL...
UM...
I MEAN...
HOW IS IT...DONE?
MR. SPOCK?
YOU'RE
THE SCIENCE OFFICER.
WHY DON'T YOU EXPLAIN IT
TO THE YOUNG LADY?
WELL,
I...CAN BELIEVE
IT'S SAFE--AHEM--
SAFE TO ASSUME
THAT THEY WOULD...
RECEIVE
THE NECESSARY...
INSTRUCTIONS.
FROM A MACHINE?
THAT I'D LIKE TO SEE.
I UNDERSTAND, VAAL.
IT SHALL BE DONE.
YOU KNOW, IF IT
WEREN'T FOR...VAAL,
THIS PLACE WOULD BE
A PARADISE.
ANY PLACE
WE CAN BE TOGETHER
IS PARADISE.
PAV...
CAN THE SHIP
REALLY BREAK AWAY?
I DON'T KNOW.
WILL WE BE ABLE
TO GET BACK ABOARD?
MARTHA, I DON'T KNOW.
BUT IF WE DO
HAVE TO STAY HERE,
WOULD IT BE SO...
VERY BAD?
NO...
NOT IF YOU'RE WITH ME.
WHY DO YOU
LOOK LIKE THAT?
THE WAY THEY TOUCHED...
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
THEY WERE NOT ANGRY.
I THINK IT WAS
PLEASANT FOR THEM.
BUT WHAT IS
TO BE GAINED?
IT IS NOT A DANCE.
IT GATHERS NO FOOD.
IT DOES NOT SERVE VAAL.
BUT...
IT DID SEEM
AS THOUGH IT WAS...
PLEASANT TO THEM.
IT IS PLEASANT, MAKORA.
YES.
THEY TOUCHED...
IN THIS WAY.
[THUNDER]
VAAL! HE IS ANGRY.
THE LAW IS PLAIN.
I HAVE GIVEN YOU
THE WORDS OF VAAL.
DO YOU BEG
THE LIGHTNING TO STRIKE?
WE SAW THE STRANGERS,
THE TWO OF THEM,
DO THIS THING.
YOU COPIED THEM?
WE MEANT NO HARM.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
VAAL SPEAKS TRULY TO ME.
THE NEWCOMERS ARE A DANGER.
TELL THE MEN OF VAAL TO
MEET ME IN THE CLEAR PLACE
WHEN THE STRANGERS
ARE ASLEEP.
IT IS VAAL'S OWN WORDS.
VAAL HAS SPOKEN TO ME.
HIS WORDS ARE TRUE.
HEAR THEM.
WE ARE TO KILL
THE STRANGERS.
KILL?
AKUTA...
WE DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
IT IS A...THING TO DO,
LIKE...LIKE FEEDING VAAL.
VAAL EXPLAINED IT TO ME.
I WILL SHOW YOU.
THIS...IS THE HEAD
OF ONE OF THE STRANGERS.
FIND--A HEAVY STICK.
COME UP FROM BEHIND
THE STRANGER
AND DO THIS.
IT IS A SIMPLE THING.
IT IS THE WORD OF VAAL.
IT WILL BE DONE...
TO ALL OF THEM...
WHEN THE SUN RETURNS
IN THE MORNING.
I AM CONCERNED, CAPTAIN.
THIS MAY NOT BE
AN IDEAL SOCIETY,
BUT IT IS A VIABLE ONE.
BONES WAS RIGHT.
THESE PEOPLE
AREN'T LIVING.
THEY'RE EXISTING.
THEY DON'T CREATE,
THEY DON'T PRODUCE,
THEY DON'T EVEN THINK.
THEY EXIST
TO SERVICE A MACHINE.
IF WE DO WHAT
IT SEEMS WE MUST,
IN MY OPINION,
IT WOULD BE
IN DIRECT VIOLATION
OF THE NONINTERFERENCE
DIRECTIVE.
THESE ARE PEOPLE...
NOT ROBOTS.
THEY SHOULD HAVE
THE OPPORTUNITY
OF CHOICE.
WE OWE IT TO THEM
TO INTERFERE.
STARFLEET COMMAND
MAY THINK OTHERWISE.
I'LL TAKE MY CHANCES.
WHY DON'T YOU
HAVE A LOOK AROUND?
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
MR. SCOTT?
HERE, SIR.
HOW IS IT GOING,
SCOTTY?
ALMOST READY, SIR. WE NEED
A HALF AN HOUR YET.
YOU REALIZE THAT
WITHIN 45 MINUTES,
THE SHIP WILL
BE PULLED DOWN INTO
THE ATMOSPHERE?
I KNOW THAT.
AS YOU SAID, THAT'S
CUTTING THINGS FINE.
YES, I--
CAPTAIN!
KIRK OUT.
WHAT IS IT?
DISTURBING.
THE PEOPLE OF VAAL SEEM
TO HAVE DISAPPEARED.
FORCE FIELD, CAPTAIN.
VAAL...
WE ARE ON
A PEACEFUL MISSION.
WE MEAN NO HARM TO YOU
OR YOUR PEOPLE.
[THUNDER]
VARIATION IN IMPULSES,
CAPTAIN.
I BELIEVE IT IS
READING US.
STRONG JUMP
ON ALL WAVELENGTHS.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
BONES!
SECOND-DEGREE BURNS.
NOT SERIOUS,
BUT I'LL BET THEY SMART.
DOCTOR, YOU HAVE
AN UNSURPASSED TALENT
FOR UNDERSTATEMENT.
MARPLE!
PUT THEM IN THE HUT.
FIND OUT
WHERE THE WOMEN ARE.
PUT THEM IN THERE, TOO.
THE GOOD DOCTOR
WAS CONCERNED
THAT THE VAALIANS
ACHIEVE TRUE HUMAN
STATURE.
I SUBMIT THERE IS
NO CAUSE FOR WORRY.
THEY'VE TAKEN
THE FIRST STEP.
THEY'VE LEARNED TO KILL.
WE'RE READY HERE, SIR.
ALL AVAILABLE POWER
HAS BEEN CHANNELED
INTO THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
WE HAVE 12 MINUTES
BEFORE ENTERING
ATMOSPHERE.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY,
PUT HER IN FULL REVERSE.
GET HER OUT OF THERE.
FULL REVERSE,
MR. KYLE, ALL ENGINES.
SIR!
CAPTAIN, WE'RE DOING IT.
WE'RE PULLING AWAY!
SCOTTY,
WHAT HAPPENED?
IT'S NO GOOD, SIR.
THERE'S ONLY A FEW SYSTEMS
RESPONDING.
CAPTAIN, WE PULLED
AWAY A LITTLE,
BUT WE GAINED...
MAYBE AN HOUR...
BUT WE BLEW ALMOST
EVERY SYSTEM IN
THE SHIP DOING IT.
THERE'S NOTHING LEFT
TO TRY AGAIN.
I GUESS YOU'LL
HAVE TO FIRE ME, SIR.
YOU'RE FIRED.
400 PEOPLE...
JIM...
THEY'LL DIE
BECAUSE I COULDN'T
SEE A WARNING SIGN.
I HAD TO
FOLLOW ORDERS,
ALWAYS ORDERS.
[GONG SOUNDS IN DISTANCE]
GET BACK IN THERE!
A FINE TIME TO RING
THE DINNER BELL.
GET BACK
IN THERE NOW!
BONES, THAT'S IT.
Chekov: BACK IN THERE. GO.
STAY WITH CHEKOV.
KEEP THOSE PEOPLE
FROM FEEDING VAAL.
DON'T LET THEM
FEED VAAL!
KEEP THEM
IN THE HUT.
MR. SPOCK.
SCOTTY, DO YOU STILL
HAVE PHASER POWER?
AYE, BUT WHAT--
LOCK ALL BANKS ON
THE COORDINATES
OF THE ENERGY FIELD
YOU LOCATED DOWN HERE.
ON MY COMMAND,
COMMENCE FIRING
ON THOSE COORDINATES.
AYE, SIR, BUT
THEY WON'T PENETRATE
THAT FORCE FIELD.
IF MY GUESS IS CORRECT,
THEY WON'T HAVE TO.
STAND BY.
VAAL CALLS TO US.
LET US GO TO HIM.
HE HUNGERS.
PLEASE.
READINGS ARE GETTING
WEAKER, CAPTAIN.
WIDE VARIATION
IN ENERGY TRANSMISSIONS,
AS THOUGH VAAL
WERE TRYING TO DRAW
ON OTHER SOURCES.
TAPPING
ITS ENERGY CELLS.
I WOULD ASSUME SO.
GOOD. THE SHIP'S
PULLING AWAY MUST
HAVE WEAKENED IT
CONSIDERING
IT HAS TO BE FED,
BUT ITS RESERVE CAPACITY
COULD HOLD OUT FOR DAYS.
IF IT HAD TO REINFORCE
ITS ENERGY FIELD TO WARD
OFF A PHASER ATTACK,
IT WOULD HAVE TO
DRAW MORE HEAVILY
ON ITS RESERVES.
MY PLAN EXACTLY.
SCOTTY.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
SCOTTY, COMMENCE FIRING
AND MAINTAIN.
MR. KYLE, ALL PHASERS
COMMENCE FIRING.
TREMENDOUS UPSURGE
IN GENERATED POWER,
CAPTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY, VAAL IS
TRYING TO REINFORCE
HIS ENERGY FIELD.
GOOD.
LET'S SEE HOW LONG
HE CAN DO IT.
[THUNDER]
Kirk:
SCOTTY! CEASE FIRE!
NO POWER GENERATION
AT ALL, CAPTAIN.
VAAL IS DEAD.
MR. SCOTT,
STATUS REPORT.
TRACTOR BEAM GONE.
POTENCY RETURNING
TO ANTIMATTER PODS.
I'LL HAVE ALL ENGINEERING
SECTIONS WORKING ON
THE CIRCUITS IMMEDIATELY.
TRANSPORTER WILL
BE READY IN AN HOUR.
SCOTTY, YOU'RE REHIRED.
AS SOON AS
THE TRANSPORTER'S FIXED,
FORM AN ENGINEERING
DETAIL WITH FULL
ANALYTICAL EQUIPMENT
AND BEAM THEM DOWN.
KIRK OUT.
CHEKOV, BONES...
LET THOSE PEOPLE GO.
BUT IT WAS VAAL WHO...
PUT THE FRUIT
ON THE TREES,
CAUSED THE RAIN TO FALL.
VAAL...
CARED FOR US.
YOU'LL LEARN TO CARE
FOR YOURSELVES
WITH OUR HELP.
AND THERE'S NO TRICK
TO PUTTING FRUIT
ON TREES.
YOU MIGHT EVEN ENJOY IT.
YOU'LL LEARN TO BUILD
FOR YOURSELVES,
THINK FOR YOURSELVES,
WORK FOR YOURSELVES,
AND WHAT YOU CREATE
IS YOURS.
THAT'S WHAT
WE CALL FREEDOM.
YOU'LL LIKE IT A LOT.
AND YOU'LL
LEARN SOMETHING
ABOUT MEN AND WOMEN,
THE WAY THEY'RE
SUPPOSED TO BE--
CARING FOR EACH OTHER,
BEING HAPPY
WITH EACH OTHER, BEING
GOOD TO EACH OTHER.
THAT'S WHAT
WE CALL...LOVE.
YOU'LL LIKE THAT,
TOO, A LOT,
YOU AND YOUR CHILDREN.
WHAT ARE CHILDREN?
THE...LITTLE ONES
THAT LOOK LIKE YOU.
JUST GO ON
THE WAY YOU'RE GOING.
YOU'LL FIND OUT.
WELL, I DON'T AGREE
WITH YOU AT ALL,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT'S NOT UNUSUAL,
DOCTOR.
HEY, JIM, I WANT YOU
TO HEAR THIS.
CAPTAIN,
I'M NOT AT ALL CERTAIN
WE DID THE CORRECT THING
ON GAMMA TRIANGULI 6.
WE PUT THOSE PEOPLE
BACK ON A NORMAL COURSE
OF SOCIAL EVOLUTION.
I SEE NOTHING WRONG
IN THAT.
WELL, THAT'S
A GOOD OBJECT
LESSON, MR. SPOCK,
AN EXAMPLE OF WHAT CAN
HAPPEN WHEN A MACHINE
BECOMES TOO EFFICIENT,
DOES TOO MUCH WORK
FOR YOU.
CAPTAIN, YOU ARE AWARE
OF THE BIBLICAL STORY
OF "GENESIS."
YES, OF COURSE. I'M
AWARE THAT ADAM AND EVE
TASTED THE APPLE
AND AS A RESULT
WERE DRIVEN
OUT OF PARADISE.
PRECISELY, CAPTAIN,
AND IN A MANNER
OF SPEAKING,
WE HAVE GIVEN
THE PEOPLE OF VAAL
THE APPLE,
THE KNOWLEDGE
OF GOOD AND EVIL,
IF YOU WILL,
AS A RESULT OF WHICH
THEY, TOO, HAVE BEEN
DRIVEN OUT OF PARADISE.
DOCTOR,
DO I UNDERSTAND
HIM CORRECTLY?
ARE YOU CASTING ME
IN THE ROLE OF SATAN?
NOT AT ALL, CAPTAIN.
IS THERE ANYONE
ON THIS SHIP WHO
EVEN REMOTELY...
LOOKS LIKE SATAN?
I AM NOT AWARE
OF ANYONE
WHO FITS THAT DESCRIPTION,
CAPTAIN.
NO, MR. SPOCK,
I DIDN'T THINK YOU WOULD.