THE DISTRESS CALL
DEFINITELY CAME
FROM ONE OF THE SOLAR
SYSTEMS IN THIS SECTOR,
CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU PINPOINT IT
ANY CLOSER, LIEUTENANT?
NEGATIVE. IT WAS
SO BADLY GARBLED
ALL WE GOT WAS
THE NAME CONSTELLATION.
THEN WE LOST IT.
[SULU]
SIR...
WE'RE NOW
WITHIN THE LIMITS
OF SYSTEM L-370,
BUT I CAN'T SEEM TO
LOCATE--
CAPTAIN, SENSORS SHOW
THIS ENTIRE SOLAR SYSTEM
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
NOTHING LEFT BUT
RUBBLE AND ASTEROIDS.
THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
THE STAR IN THIS SYSTEM
IS STILL INTACT.
ONLY A NOVA COULD
DESTROY LIKE THAT.
NONETHELESS, CAPTAIN,
SENSORS SHOW
NOTHING BUT DEBRIS
WHERE WE CHARTED
7 PLANETS LAST YEAR.
CONTINUE
SEARCH PATTERN.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
ENTERING LIMITS
OF SYSTEM L-374, SIR.
SCANNERS SHOW THE SAME
EVIDENCE OF DESTRUCTION.
EVERY SOLAR SYSTEM
IN THIS SECTOR
BLASTED TO RUBBLE.
STILL NO SIGN
OF THE CONSTELLATION.
MATT DECKER'S
IN COMMAND.
WHAT COULD HAVE
HAPPENED TO HIM?
CAPTAIN, THE TWO
INNERMOST PLANETS
OF THIS SYSTEM
APPEAR TO BE INTACT.
SIR, I'M PICKING
UP A SHIP'S
DISASTER BEACON.
TRY TO RAISE IT,
LIEUTENANT.
I HAVE IT ON
THE SENSORS, CAPTAIN.
BY CONFIGURATION--
A STARSHIP.
STOPPED IN SPACE.
SHE APPEARS TO
BE DRIFTING.
NO ANSWER,
CAPTAIN.
ALL I GET IS
THE AUTOMATIC
BEACON.
SENSORS NOT RECORDING
NORMAL ENERGY OUTPUT.
APPROACH COURSE,
MR. SULU.
IT'S THE CONSTELLATION.
LOOK AT THAT.
SHE MAY
HAVE BEEN WRECKED
BY WHATEVER DESTROYED
THESE SOLAR SYSTEMS.
SHE WAS ATTACKED.
RED ALERT!
MAN YOUR
BATTLE STATIONS!
RED ALERT!
MAN YOUR
BATTLE STATIONS!
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
MR. SULU?
ALL PHASER BANKS
MANNED AND READY, SIR.
GOOD. INITIATE
A FULL SENSOR SCAN
OF THE IMMEDIATE AREA
FOR ANY OTHER VESSEL.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT PALMER.
I CAN'T RAISE
THE CONSTELLATION, SIR.
I'M STILL GETTING
THE DISTRESS BEACON,
BUT THERE'S HEAVY
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE.
IT'S ALMOST
BLOCKING THE SIGNAL.
KEEP TRYING.
MR. SPOCK, FULL
EVALUATION OF THE DAMAGE
TO THE CONSTELLATION.
ALL POWER PLANTS DEAD.
RESERVE ENERGY BANKS
OPERABLE AT A VERY
LOW POWER LEVEL.
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS?
ALSO OPERATIVE
AT A LOW POWER LEVEL.
THE ENTIRE BRIDGE IS
DAMAGED AND UNINHABITABLE.
THE REST OF THE SHIP
SEEMS ABLE TO SUSTAIN LIFE.
RADIATION LEVELS?
NORMAL, BUT SUBSPACE
INTERFERENCE MAKES
READINGS DIFFICULT.
NO OTHER VESSELS
IN THE AREA, CAPTAIN.
ALL SCANNERS
SHOW CLEAR.
ALL HANDS
GO TO YELLOW ALERT.
STAND BY
BATTLE STATIONS.
LIEUTENANT, HAVE
DR. McCOY, MR. SCOTT,
AND A DAMAGE CONTROL
PARTY REPORT TO ME IN
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AYE, SIR.
WE'RE GOING
TO BOARD HER.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU'RE IN COMMAND.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
RADIATION LEVEL
NORMAL.
ATMOSPHERIC PRESSURE
11 POUNDS PER SQUARE INCH.
THE FILTRATION
SYSTEMS ARE
OUT, SIR.
THE WHOLE COMMUNICATION
SYSTEM LOOKS TO BE
SHORTED OUT, TOO, SIR.
SCOTTY, CHECK
THE PHASER BANKS.
SEE IF THEY'VE
BEEN FIRED.
BONES, YOU
COME WITH ME.
COME ALONG, LADS.
WHAT A MESS.
NO CLUTTER,
NO HALF-EMPTY
CUPS OF COFFEE.
WHATEVER HAPPENED
DIDN'T HAPPEN
WITHOUT A WARNING.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
DID IT, SIR?
I DON'T KNOW, LAD.
BUT I WANT
A FULL STRUCTURAL AND
CONTROL DAMAGE CHECK,
AND I'M GOING TO HAVE
A LOOK AT THOSE ENGINES.
THE CREW WASN'T ABDUCTED,
THEY JUST LEFT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE,
SPOCK HERE.
NO SURVIVORS,
NO BODIES EITHER.
IS IT POSSIBLE THEY
WERE BEAMED DOWN
TO ONE OF THE TWO PLANETS?
IMPROBABLE, CAPTAIN.
THE SURFACE TEMPERATURE
OF THE INNER PLANET IS
THAT OF MOLTEN LEAD.
THE OTHER HAS AN
ATMOSPHERE POISONOUS
TO HUMAN LIFE.
WE'LL CONTINUE OUR SEARCH.
KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, I CHECKED
THE ENGINES.
THE WARP DRIVE IS
A HOPELESS PILE
OF JUNK.
THE IMPULSE ENGINES
ARE NOT TOO BADLY OFF.
WE OUGHT TO BE ABLE
TO DO SOMETHING
WITH THEM.
PHASER BANKS?
EXHAUSTED. THEY
DIDN'T GIVE UP
WITHOUT A BATTLE.
BUT WHERE ARE THEY?
I CAN'T IMAGINE
A MAN LIKE MATT DECKER
ABANDONING SHIP
WHILE HIS LIFE SUPPORT
SYSTEMS ARE STILL
OPERATIVE.
THE COMPUTER SYSTEM
IS STILL INTACT.
WE CAN PLAY BACK
THE DUPLICATE
CAPTAIN'S LOG
FROM THE AUXILIARY
CONTROL ROOM.
MATT.
IT'S JIM KIRK.
COMMODORE?
COMMODORE DECKER?
MATT?
MATT.
KIRK.
IT'S JIM KIRK.
WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOUR SHIP, MATT?
MY SHIP...
ATTACKED!
THAT--THAT THING.
WHAT THING?
WHAT WAS IT?
THAT--
ANSWER ME!
WHAT WAS IT?
WHAT HAPPENED, MATT?
JIM, GIVE HIM
A MINUTE.
HE'S IN A STATE
OF SHOCK.
READY WITH
THE DUPLICATE
LOG, SIR.
GO.
Matt Decker:
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 4202.1.
EXCEPTIONALLY HEAVY
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE
STILL PREVENTS OUR
CONTACTING STARFLEET
TO INFORM THEM OF
THE DESTROYED SOLAR SYSTEMS
WE HAVE ENCOUNTERED.
WE ARE NOW
ENTERING SYSTEM L-374.
SCIENCE OFFICER MASADA
REPORTS THE FOURTH PLANET
SEEMS TO BE BREAKING UP.
WE ARE GOING
TO INVESTIGATE.
FOURTH PLANET.
ONLY 2 LEFT NOW.
SCOTTY, PULL THE
MICROTAPES FROM THE
SENSOR MEMORY BANKS
AND BEAM THEM ABOARD
TO SPOCK.
I WANT A FULL
ANALYSIS--A COMPLETE
REPORT OF WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN THEY WENT IN
ON THAT PLANET.
WE TRIED TO
CONTACT STARFLEET.
UH, NO ONE HEARD.
NO ONE!
WE COULDN'T RUN.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR CREW?
OH, I HAD TO BEAM THEM DOWN.
WE--WE WERE DEAD.
NO POWER,
OUR PHASERS USELESS.
I STAYED BEHIND,
THE LAST MAN.
THE CAPTAIN,
THE LAST MAN
ABOARD THE SHIP.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO DO, ISN'T IT?
AND THEN IT HIT AGAIN,
AND THE, UH,
TRANSPORTER WENT OUT.
THEY WERE DOWN THERE,
AND I'M--I'M UP HERE.
WHAT HIT?
WHAT ATTACKED YOU?
THEY SAY THERE'S
NO DEVIL, JIM,
BUT THERE IS.
RIGHT OUT OF HELL,
I SAW IT.
MATT,
WHERE'S YOUR CREW?
ON THE THIRD PLANET.
THERE IS
NO THIRD PLANET.
DON'T YOU THINK
I KNOW THAT?
THERE WAS,
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
THEY CALLED ME.
THEY BEGGED ME FOR HELP,
400 OF THEM.
I COULDN'T.
I--I COULDN'T.
CAPTAIN, WASHBURN
HAS OUR REPORT.
GO.
WE MADE A COMPLETE
CHECK ON STRUCTURAL
AND CONTROL DAMAGE, SIR.
AS FAR AS WE CAN TELL,
SOMETHING CRASHED
THROUGH THE DEFLECTORS
AND KNOCKED
OUT THE GENERATORS.
SOMEHOW THE ANTIMATTER
IN THE WARP DRIVE PODS
HAS BEEN DEACTIVATED.
DEACTIVATED.
SCOTTY,
COULD SOME
KIND OF...
GENERAL ENERGY
DAMPENING FIELD DO THAT,
AND WOULD THE SAME
TYPE OF THING
ACCOUNT FOR THE HEAVY
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE?
AYE, THAT
ALL ADDS UP.
BUT WHAT
SORT OF A THING
COULD DO ALL THAT?
IF YOU'D SEEN IT,
YOU'D KNOW.
THE WHOLE THING
IS A WEAPON.
IT MUST BE.
WHAT DOES
IT LOOK LIKE?
WELL, IT'S--IT'S
MILES LONG,
WITH A MAW
THAT COULD SWALLOW
A DOZEN STARSHIPS.
IT DESTROYS PLANETS,
CHOPS THEM INTO RUBBLE.
WHAT IS IT,
AN ALIEN SHIP?
OR IS IT ALIVE--
BOTH OR NEITHER.
I DON'T KNOW.
MATT, YOUR LOG STATED
THAT THE FOURTH PLANET
WAS BREAKING UP.
YOU WENT IN
TO INVESTIGATE.
WE SAW
THIS THING HOVERING
OVER THE PLANET,
SLICING OUT CHUNKS OF IT
WITH A FORCE BEAM.
DID YOU RUN
A SCANNER CHECK ON IT?
WHAT KIND OF A BEAM?
PURE ANTIPROTON.
ABSOLUTELY PURE.
[BEEP BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
UNABLE TO RAISE
STARFLEET COMMAND
DUE TO HEAVY
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE.
ATTEMPTING TO REMEDY.
WHAT ABOUT THE
CONSTELLATION'S TAPES?
SHE WAS ATTACKED BY
WHAT APPEARS TO BE
ESSENTIALLY...
A ROBOT,
AN AUTOMATED WEAPON
OF IMMENSE SIZE AND POWER.
ITS APPARENT FUNCTION
IS TO SMASH PLANETS
TO RUBBLE
AND THEN DIGEST
THE DEBRIS FOR FUEL.
IT IS, THEREFORE,
SELF-SUSTAINING
AS LONG AS THERE
ARE PLANETARY BODIES
FOR IT TO FEED ON.
A ROBOT WEAPON
THAT PURPOSELY DESTROYS
ENTIRE SOLAR SYSTEMS.
WHY?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, MR. SULU
HAS COMPUTED THE PATH
OF THE MACHINE,
USING THE DESTROYED
SOLAR SYSTEMS
AS A BASE COURSE.
PROJECTING BACK
ON OUR STAR CHARTS,
WE FIND THAT IT
CAME FROM OUTSIDE,
FROM ANOTHER GALAXY.
WHAT IS THE PROJECTED
COURSE OF THIS THING?
IF IT FOLLOWS
ITS PRESENT PATH,
IT WILL GO THROUGH
THE MOST DENSELY
POPULATED SECTION
OF OUR GALAXY.
THANK YOU.
STAND BY, MR. SPOCK.
KIRK OUT.
THIS WHOLE THING
IS INCREDIBLE.
A ROBOT.
A MACHINE LIKE
THAT--WHO WOULD
BUILD IT?
WE DON'T KNOW.
AN ALIEN RACE,
APPARENTLY FROM
ANOTHER GALAXY.
BUT WHY?
BONES...
DID YOU EVER HEAR
OF A DOOMSDAY MACHINE?
NO. I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT A MECHANIC.
IT'S A WEAPON
BUILT PRIMARILY
AS A BLUFF.
IT'S NEVER
MEANT TO BE USED.
SO STRONG, IT COULD DESTROY
BOTH SIDES IN A WAR.
SOMETHING LIKE
THE OLD H-BOMB
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE.
THAT'S WHAT
I THINK THIS IS...
A DOOMSDAY MACHINE
THAT SOMEBODY USED
IN A WAR
UNCOUNTED YEARS AGO.
THEY DON'T EXIST ANYMORE,
BUT THE MACHINE
IS STILL DESTROYING.
OH, FORGET ABOUT
YOUR THEORIES!
THAT THING'S ON
THE WAY TO THE HEART
OF OUR GALAXY.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO ABOUT IT?
TAKE IT EASY.
THE FIRST THING
WE'RE GONNA DO
IS GET YOU BACK
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
OH, NO. I STAY HERE.
I'M NOT LEAVING MY SHIP!
THERE'S NO SHIP TO LEAVE!
IT'S A DEAD HULK!
WE'LL TAKE HER IN TOW.
I'LL STAY ONBOARD
AND GET HER READY.
YOU GO BACK TO THE
ENTERPRISE WITH THE DOCTOR
AND LET HIM HELP YOU.
IT'S JUST THAT
I--I NEVER LOST
A COMMAND BEFORE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
HAVE THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
BEAM DR. McCOY
AND COMMODORE DECKER
ONBOARD IMMEDIATELY.
RED ALERT. RED ALERT.
COME ON.
IT CAME UP ON
US FAST, CAPTAIN,
BUT WE SEEM ABLE
TO MAINTAIN OUR DISTANCE.
WE'RE BLIND HERE.
WHAT'S IT LOOK LIKE?
IT LOOKS VERY MUCH
LIKE COMMODORE DECKER'S
PLANET KILLER.
AND IT IS PURSUING US.
WE ARE MORE MANEUVERABLE,
BUT IT IS GAINING ON US.
SENSORS INDICATE SOME KIND
OF TOTAL CONVERSION DRIVE.
NO EVIDENCE OF LIFE,
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE
LEVEL INCREDIBLY HIGH.
WHATEVER IT IS,
WE CAN'T LET IT GO BEYOND US
TO THE NEXT SOLAR SYSTEM.
WE HAVE TO STOP IT.
IF IT'S A ROBOT,
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF DEACTIVATING IT?
I WOULD SAY NONE,
CAPTAIN.
THE ENERGY GENERATED
BY OUR POWER CELLS
SEEMS TO ATTRACT IT.
I DOUBT WE COULD
MANEUVER CLOSE
ENOUGH
WITHOUT DRAWING
A DIRECT ATTACK
UPON OURSELVES.
I ALSO BELIEVE
THE NATURE OF THIS
MACHINE
PRECLUDES THE
POSSIBILITY OF
EASY ACCESS
TO ITS CONTROL
MECHANISMS.
IT'S CLOSING
ON US, MR. SPOCK.
CLOSING, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT. LOWER YOUR
DEFLECTOR SCREENS
LONG ENOUGH
TO BEAM US ABOARD.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
STAND BY TO BEAM
LANDING PARTY ABOARD.
READY
TO BEAM, SIR.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
EVASIVE ACTION,
MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
DAMAGE REPORT--
ALL STATIONS.
MR. SPOCK,
THE TRANSPORTER'S OUT.
EFFECT REPAIRS.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
COME IN PLEASE.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN,
WE'VE BEEN ATTACKED.
TRANSPORTER IS DAMAGED.
WE'RE TAKING EVASIVE ACTION.
MR. SPOCK,
COMMUNICATION'S DAMAGED.
WE'RE UNABLE TO OVERRIDE
INTERFERENCE.
DAMAGE IN COMMUNICATIONS,
CAPTAIN. INTERFERENCE WILL--
[STATIC]
SPOCK?
COME IN, SPOCK.
[STATIC]
WE'RE STUCK,
BLIND, AND DEAF.
AND PARALYZED.
NO POWER.
WELL, WE JUST
CAN'T STAND AROUND
WHILE OUR SHIP
IS BEING ATTACKED.
SCOTTY, YOU'VE
GOT TO GET ME SOME
MANEUVERING POWER.
I CAN'T REPAIR
THE WARP DRIVE
WITHOUT--
THEN GET ME IMPULSE POWER--
HALF-SPEED, QUARTER-SPEED,
ANYTHING.
IF WE GET THIS HULK MOVING,
MAYBE WE CAN DO SOMETHING.
AYE. THE IMPULSE
ENGINES ARE STILL
IN FAIR SHAPE.
I MIGHT COAX THEM.
THEN GET MOVING.
COME ALONG, LAD.
WASHBURN,
YOU GET IN THERE.
LET'S SEE WHAT WE CAN DO
ABOUT THIS VIEWING SCREEN.
I'VE GOT TO FIND OUT
WHAT'S HAPPENING OUT THERE.
NO CASUALTIES,
MR. SPOCK.
HOW ARE WE DOING?
WE HAVE OUTRUN IT,
DOCTOR.
STATUS REPORT.
IMPULSE AND WARP
ENGINES OPERATIVE,
TRANSPORTER
AND COMMUNICATIONS
UNDER REPAIR.
RANDOM CHANCE SEEMS
TO HAVE OPERATED
IN OUR FAVOR.
IN PLAIN,
NONVULCAN ENGLISH--
WE'VE BEEN LUCKY.
I BELIEVE
I SAID THAT, DOCTOR.
IT'S VEERING OFF,
BACK ON COURSE FOR
THE NEXT SOLAR SYSTEM--
THE RIGEL COLONY, SIR.
EVIDENTLY PROGRAMMED
TO IGNORE ANYTHING
AS SMALL
AS A SHIP BEYOND
A CERTAIN RADIUS.
WE'LL MAINTAIN
A DISCREET DISTANCE
AND CIRCLE BACK TO
PICK UP THE CAPTAIN.
YOU CAN'T LET
THAT THING REACH RIGEL.
WHY, MILLIONS OF INNOCENT
PEOPLE WOULD DIE.
I'M AWARE OF THE RIGEL
SYSTEM'S POPULATION,
COMMODORE,
BUT WE ARE
ONLY ONE SHIP.
OUR DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
ARE STRAINED,
OUR SUBSPACE TRANSMITTER
IS USELESS.
LOGICALLY,
OUR PRIMARY DUTY
IS TO SURVIVE
IN ORDER TO WARN
STARFLEET COMMAND.
OUR PRIMARY DUTY
IS TO MAINTAIN LIFE
AND THE SAFETY OF
FEDERATION PLANETS.
DO YOU DENY THAT?
MR. SULU,
YOU WILL LAY IN
AN EVASIVE COURSE
BACK TO
THE CONSTELLATION.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
BELAY THAT
LAST ORDER, HELMSMAN.
180-DEGREE TURN,
HARD ABOUT.
WE'RE GOING TO ATTACK.
YOU WILL CARRY OUT
MY LAST ORDER,
MR. SULU.
MR. SPOCK,
I'M OFFICIALLY
NOTIFYING YOU
THAT I'M
EXERCISING MY OPTION
UNDER REGULATIONS
AS A STARFLEET COMMODORE
AND THAT I AM ASSUMING
COMMAND OF THE ENTERPRISE.
YOU HAVE
THE RIGHT TO DO SO,
BUT I WOULD
ADVISE AGAINST IT.
THAT THING
MUST BE DESTROYED.
YOU TRIED TO DESTROY IT
ONCE BEFORE, COMMODORE.
THE RESULT
WAS A WRECKED SHIP
AND A DEAD CREW.
I MADE A MISTAKE THEN.
WE WERE TOO FAR AWAY.
THIS TIME I'M GOING TO
HIT IT WITH FULL PHASERS
AT POINTBLANK RANGE.
SENSORS SHOW
THE OBJECT'S HULL
IS SOLID NEUTRONIUM.
A SINGLE SHIP
CANNOT COMBAT IT.
MR. SPOCK,
THAT WILL BE ALL.
YOU HAVE BEEN
RELIEVED OF COMMAND.
DON'T FORCE ME
TO RELIEVE YOU
OF DUTY AS WELL.
YOU CAN'T LET HIM
DO THIS, SPOCK.
DOCTOR, YOU
ARE OUT OF LINE.
SO ARE YOU...
SIR.
WELL, SPOCK?
UNFORTUNATELY,
STARFLEET ORDER
104, SECTION B,
LEAVES ME
NO ALTERNATIVE.
PARAGRAPH 1-A
CLEARLY STATES--
TO BLAZES
WITH REGULATIONS!
YOU CAN'T LET HIM
TAKE COMMAND WHEN
YOU KNOW HE'S WRONG!
IF YOU CAN CERTIFY
COMMODORE DECKER
MEDICALLY OR
PSYCHOLOGICALLY
UNFIT FOR COMMAND,
I CAN RELIEVE HIM
UNDER SECTION C.
I'LL CERTIFY THAT
RIGHT NOW.
YOU'LL ALSO BE ASKED
TO PRODUCE
YOUR MEDICAL RECORDS
TO PROVE IT.
NOW, YOU KNOW
I HAVEN'T HAD TIME
TO RUN AN
EXAMINATION ON HIM.
THEN YOUR
STATEMENT WOULD NOT
BE CONSIDERED VALID.
YOU MAY LEAVE
THE BRIDGE, DOCTOR.
WHAT ABOUT THE CAPTAIN?
WE CAN'T LEAVE--
DOCTOR...
YOU MAY
LEAVE THE BRIDGE.
SPOCK,
DO SOMETHING!
MR. SPOCK KNOWS HIS DUTY
UNDER REGULATIONS, DOCTOR.
DO YOU?
HARD ABOUT, HELMSMAN.
COURSE...
32 DEGREES, MARK 10.
DEFLECTORS AT FULL POWER.
READY ON
MAIN PHASER BANKS.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
[BEEP BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN,
THE IMPULSE ENGINES'
CONTROL CIRCUITS
ARE FUSED SOLID.
WHAT ABOUT THE WARP DRIVE
CONTROL CIRCUITS?
AYE, WE CAN
CROSS-CONNECT
THE CONTROLS,
BUT IT'LL MAKE THE SHIP
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
FOR ONE MAN TO HANDLE.
YOU WORRY ABOUT
YOUR MIRACLES, SCOTTY;
I'LL WORRY ABOUT MINE.
GET TO WORK.
AYE, SIR.
WASHBURN, TRY
THE 2-G-6 CIRCUIT.
CLOSING FAST.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
AT FULL POWER.
THEY CAN'T TAKE
MUCH MORE OF THIS.
HELMSMAN,
HOLD YOUR COURSE.
STAND BY
ALL PHASER BANKS.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
DEFLECTORS HOLDING,
BUT WEAKENING.
WE MUST RETREAT,
COMMODORE.
THE ENERGY DRAIN--
I'M IN COMMAND
HERE, MR. SPOCK.
MAINTAIN YOUR
COURSE, HELMSMAN.
GET US IN CLOSER.
READY TO
GIVE IT A TRY?
UH, JUST
ONE MINUTE, SIR.
SCOTTY, HOW YOU DOING?
CONTROLS ARE
ALL HOOKED UP, SIR.
WE SHOULD HAVE SOME
POWER FOR YOU SOON.
TRY IT NOW,
CAPTAIN.
YES, I THINK--
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON?
FIRE!
DIRECT HIT.
JUST...BOUNCED OFF.
COMMODORE, I URGENTLY
RECOMMEND IMMEDIATE
WITHDRAWAL.
RECOMMENDATION NOTED.
MAINTAIN COURSE!
FIRE!
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
MR. SPOCK, COME IN.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTTY,
WHERE'S THAT POWER?
COMING, SIR.
IF I PUSH THESE
IMPULSE ENGINES TOO HARD
IN THE CONDITION THEY'RE IN,
THEY'LL BLOW APART.
WASHBURN, GO DOWN
TO ENGINEERING.
ASSIST MR. SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
SCOTTY...
PUSH IT RIGHT
TO THE EDGE.
THIS SHIP HAS GOT
TO MANEUVER.
AYE, SIR.
SIR,
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
ARE GONE.
SIR, DECK 7
REPORTS POWER FAILURE
IN MAIN ENERGIZERS.
IMPLEMENTING
EMERGENCY PROCEDURES.
[EXPLOSION]
SEVERE CASUALTIES
REPORTED ON DECKS
3 AND 4.
DAMAGE CONTROL PARTY
SEALING OFF INNER-HULL
RUPTURE.
[EXPLOSION]
[P.A. SYSTEM]
AG SECTION
ACKNOWLEDGING.
IS STABILIZED.
ALL DECKS, THIS IS
BRIDGE ENGINEERING.
IT HAS CEASED FIRE.
WE'RE BEING HELD
IN A TRACTOR BEAM.
WE'RE BEING PULLED
INSIDE, COMMODORE.
YOU MUST
VEER OFF.
MAINTAIN PHASER FIRE,
HELMSMAN.
WE'VE LOST WARP POWER.
IF WE DON'T BREAK
THE TRACTOR BEAM
WITHIN 60 SECONDS,
WE NEVER WILL.
BUT DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND?
WE'VE GOT
TO DESTROY IT!
THAT, SIR,
IS ILLOGICAL.
IT IS SUICIDE.
ATTEMPTED SUICIDE
WOULD BE PROOF
THAT YOU ARE
PSYCHOLOGICALLY
UNFIT FOR COMMAND.
IF YOU DON'T
VEER OFF,
I SHALL
RELIEVE YOU
ON THAT BASIS.
VEER OFF!
EMERGENCY
IMPULSE POWER.
WE CAN'T
BREAK LOOSE!
WE NEED
MORE POWER!
WE HAVEN'T
GOT IT!
WE'RE BEING
PULLED INSIDE!
SCOTTY, GIVE ME
THAT POWER.
YOU'VE GOT IT, CAPTAIN--
JUST ENOUGH TO MOVE US.
I CAN'T DO BETTER.
THAT'LL DO.
FULL AHEAD,
MR. SCOTT!
[ENGINES WHINE]
[ENGINES GAIN POWER]
THAT'S IT, MR. SCOTT.
KEEP THAT POWER COMING.
FULL POWER ASTERN.
AYE, SIR.
WE STILL
CAN'T MOVE.
KEEP POURING IT ON,
SCOTTY.
CAPTAIN,
I STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT WE'RE DOING.
WE'RE MOVING.
THE ENTERPRISE ISN'T.
MAYBE THAT THING
WILL SEE US
AND LET
THE ENTERPRISE GO.
IF I ONLY HAD
SOME PHASERS.
PHASERS?
YOU'VE GOT 'EM.
I HAVE ONE BANK
RECHARGED.
SCOTTY,
YOU'VE JUST EARNED
YOUR PAY
FOR THE WEEK.
STAND BY.
FIRE PHASERS.
WE'RE LOOSE,
COMMODORE.
GOOD BOY, JIM.
BETWEEN THE TWO OF US,
WE'LL KILL THAT THING.
MR. SCOTT,
IT WORKED. GREAT.
I THINK IT'S GREAT.
SCOTTY, GET US OUT OF HERE.
IT'S CLOSING FAST
ON THE CONSTELLATION.
STANDING BY, SIR.
COMMODORE,
I SUGGEST--
KIRK PULLED US
OUT OF THERE
BY DISTRACTING IT.
NOW IT'S OUR TURN.
FIRE PHASERS.
WE DID IT!
HARD ABOUT.
GIVE ME SOME DISTANCE.
WE'RE MOVING AWAY,
COMMODORE.
THIS MACHINE
SEEMS TO HAVE
A PROGRAM-DEFENSIVE
SPHERE.
ANY ENERGY SOURCE
ENTERING THAT FIELD
IS SUBJECT TO ATTACK.
MR. SPOCK,
STATUS REPORT.
WARP DRIVE
AND DEFLECTORS
WILL BE OUT
FOR A SOLAR DAY.
REPAIRS PROCEEDING
ON TRANSPORTER
AND COMMUNICATIONS.
IT'S CLOSING WITH US
AGAIN, SIR.
MAINTAIN SPEED
AND DISTANCE.
IT'S SUCKING IN
SPACE RUBBLE FROM
THOSE DESTROYED PLANETS,
REFUELING ITSELF.
WE CAN MAINTAIN
THIS SPEED FOR ONLY
SEVEN HOURS
BEFORE WE EXHAUST
OUR FUEL,
BUT IT CAN REFUEL
ITSELF INDEFINITELY.
THEN WE'LL HAVE TO
FIGHT IT NOW,
BEFORE IT GETS
ANY STRONGER.
ILLOGICAL.
WE CANNOT DESTROY IT,
THEREFORE WE CANNOT
SAVE RIGEL.
WE MUST TRANSPORT
THE CAPTAIN AND THE OTHERS
FROM THE CONSTELLATION
AND ESCAPE THIS THING'S
SUBSPACE INTERFERENCE
IN ORDER TO WARN
STARFLEET COMMAND.
MR. SPOCK...
WE'VE PIERCED
THE INTERFERENCE
LOCALLY.
CAN YOU RAISE STARFLEET?
NO, SIR, BUT I'VE GOT
SHIP-TO-SHIP
COMMUNICATIONS BACK.
PICKING UP CAPTAIN KIRK.
ON AUDIO, LIEUTENANT.
ENTERPRISE. ENTERPRISE,
COME IN.
MR. SPOCK, I AM
STILL IN COMMAND,
AND I WILL SPEAK
FOR THIS SHIP.
ENTERPRISE
TO KIRK.
COMMODORE DECKER
SPEAKING.
MATT. WHAT'S GOING ON?
GIVE ME MR. SPOCK.
I'M IN COMMAND
HERE, JIM.
WHAT HAPPENED TO SPOCK?
NOTHING. I ASSUMED
COMMAND ACCORDING
TO REGULATIONS,
SINCE YOUR FIRST
OFFICER
WAS
RELUCTANT TO TAKE
AGGRESSIVE ACTION--
YOU MEAN YOU'RE THE
LUNATIC WHO'S RESPONSIBLE
FOR ALMOST
DESTROYING MY SHIP?
YOU ARE SPEAKING
TO A SENIOR
OFFICER, KIRK.
GIVE ME SPOCK.
I TOLD YOU,
I AM IN COMMAND
HERE,
ACCORDING TO EVERY
RULE IN THE BOOK,
CAPTAIN.
IF YOU HAVE ANYTHING
TO SAY AT ALL,
YOU WILL SAY IT
TO ME.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING
I WANT TO SAY
TO YOU, COMMODORE--
GET MY SHIP
OUT OF THERE.
MR. SPOCK,
SHIP STATUS.
COMMODORE.
DOWN HERE.
WARP DRIVE OUT.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS DOWN.
TRANSPORTER
UNDER REPAIR.
WE ARE ON EMERGENCY
IMPULSE POWER.
HOW LONG TO REPAIR
WARP DRIVE?
AT LEAST ONE SOLAR DAY.
AT OUR PRESENT RATE
OF CONSUMPTION,
WE'LL EXHAUST
OUR IMPULSE POWER
LONG BEFORE THEN.
IT'S GAINING ON US, SIR.
TAKE EVASIVE ACTION,
MR. SULU.
I TOLD YOU, I AM
IN COMMAND HERE,
AND I WILL GIVE
THE ORDERS, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE GOING TO
TURN AND ATTACK.
NOT WITH MY SHIP,
YOU DON'T.
MR. SPOCK, RELIEVE
COMMODORE DECKER IMMEDIATELY.
THAT'S A DIRECT ORDER.
YOU CAN'T RELIEVE ME,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
ACCORDING TO
REGULATIONS--
BLAST REGULATIONS!
MR. SPOCK, I ORDER YOU
TO ASSUME COMMAND
ON MY PERSONAL AUTHORITY
AS CAPTAIN OF THE ENTERPRISE.
COMMODORE DECKER,
YOU ARE RELIEVED
OF COMMAND.
I DON'T RECOGNIZE
YOUR AUTHORITY
TO RELIEVE ME!
YOU MAY FILE
A FORMAL PROTEST
WITH STARFLEET COMMAND,
ASSUMING WE SURVIVE
TO REACH A STARBASE.
BUT YOU ARE RELIEVED.
COMMODORE, I DO NOT WISH
TO PLACE YOU UNDER ARREST.
YOU WOULDN'T DARE.
YOU'RE BLUFFING.
VULCANS NEVER BLUFF.
NO.
NO, I DON'T SUPPOSE
THAT THEY DO.
VERY WELL, MR. SPOCK.
THE BRIDGE IS YOURS.
CAPTAIN, I'VE ASSUMED
COMMAND.
GOOD. NOW,
MR. SPOCK--
ONE MOMENT, SIR.
COMMODORE.
I BELIEVE
YOU'RE SCHEDULED
FOR MEDICAL EXAMINATION.
MR. MONTGOMERY.
SIR.
YOU WILL ACCOMPANY
THE COMMODORE
TO SICK BAY.
AYE, SIR.
COMMODORE?
MR. SULU,
CHANGE COURSE.
7-0-MARK-2-1.
MARK-21, SIR.
CAPTAIN,
WE ARE TAKING
AN EVASIVE COURSE
BACK TO YOU.
WE WILL TRY TO STAY
AHEAD OF THE OBJECT
UNTIL WE CAN
TRANSPORT YOU ABOARD.
FINE. JUST MAKE SURE YOU
STAY AHEAD OF IT.
[COUGH]
[SCOTT]
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YES, SCOTTY?
I'VE HOOKED IN
SHIP'S COMMUNICATION.
THE BEST I CAN GIVE YOU
ON IMPULSE IS 1/3 POWER.
THE SHIELDS ARE UP,
BUT THEY WON'T LAST LONG.
KEEP IT GOING, SCOTTY.
KEEP IT GOING.
MR. SPOCK.
YES, SIR.
I'M PLOTTING
AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
WILL RENDEZVOUS WITH YOU
AT 14:13.7 HOURS.
[BEEP BEEP]
MR. SPOCK, SOMEONE'S
OPENING THE SHUTTLECRAFT
BAY DOORS.
SHUT THEM, MR. SULU.
IT'S TOO LATE, SIR.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
WHY ARE YOU LAUNCHING
A SHUTTLECRAFT?
WHOEVER IT IS, CAPTAIN,
HAS NO AUTHORIZATION.
LIEUTENANT, RAISE
THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
ENTERPRISE
TO SHUTTLECRAFT.
COME IN, SHUTTLECRAFT.
ENTERPRISE
TO SHUTTLECRAFT.
COME IN,
SHUTTLECRAFT.
SHUTTLECRAFT
TO ENTERPRISE.
DECKER HERE.
COMMODORE,
I MUST INSIST
THAT YOU RETURN
TO THE SHIP.
YOU SAID IT
YOURSELF, SPOCK--
THERE IS NO WAY
TO BLAST
THROUGH THE HULL
OF THAT MACHINE,
SO I'M GOING
TO TAKE THIS THING
RIGHT DOWN ITS THROAT.
THIS IS KIRK. MATT,
YOU'LL BE KILLED.
I'VE BEEN PREPARED
FOR DEATH
EVER SINCE I--
EVER SINCE
I KILLED MY CREW.
NO ONE EXPECTS YOU TO DIE
FOR AN ERROR IN JUDGMENT.
THE COMMANDER
IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE LIVES
OF HIS CREW...
AND FOR THEIR DEATHS.
WELL...
I SHOULD HAVE DIED
WITH MINE.
YOU CANNOT SUCCEED,
COMMODORE.
YOUR ONLY LOGICAL
ALTERNATIVE
IS TO RETURN
TO THE SHIP.
MATT.
MATT, LISTEN TO ME.
YOU CAN'T THROW
YOUR LIFE AWAY LIKE THIS.
MATT, YOU'RE
A STARSHIP COMMANDER.
THAT MAKES YOU
A VALUABLE COMMODITY.
WE NEED YOU...
YOUR EXPERIENCE,
YOUR JUDGMENT.
MATT!
WE'RE STRONGER WITH YOU
THAN WITHOUT YOU!
HE'S GONE.
CONSTELLATION,
COME IN, PLEASE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
KIRK HERE.
SIR.
MAY I OFFER
MY CONDOLENCES
ON THE DEATH
OF YOUR FRIEND.
IT IS MOST REGRETTABLE.
IT'S REGRETTABLE THAT
HE DIED FOR NOTHING.
MR. SPOCK, SENSORS
INDICATE A MINUTE DROP
IN THE MACHINE'S
POWER EMANATIONS.
DO YOU THINK
THE SHUTTLECRAFT
EXPLOSION
MIGHT HAVE DONE
SOME DAMAGE?
Kirk:
WHAT ABOUT THAT, SPOCK?
IS IT POSSIBLE?
DROP IN POWER
IS DEFINITE,
CAPTAIN...
BUT NEGLIGIBLE.
THE OBJECT IS
STILL PURSING US,
THEREBY
CAUSING US TO DRAIN
OUR POWER RESERVE
AT A MUCH
GREATER RATE.
MR. SPOCK,
THE TRANSPORTER
IS NOW OPERATIONAL.
TRANSPORTER OPERATIONAL,
CAPTAIN.
SHALL WE BEAM YOU
ABOARD?
NEGATIVE.
MR. SCOTT AND I
WILL STAY HERE,
BUT BEAM THE DAMAGE
CONTROL PARTY ABOARD.
CAPTAIN, THERE IS
LITTLE TO BE GAINED
BY STAYING ABOARD
THE CONSTELLATION.
EXCEPT POSSIBLY...
THE DESTRUCTION
OF THAT THING OUT THERE.
CARRY OUT YOUR ORDERS,
MR. SPOCK.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
BEAM DAMAGE CONTROL PARTY
ABOARD.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
SPOCK, LISTEN.
MAYBE MATT DECKER
DIDN'T DIE FOR NOTHING.
HE HAD THE RIGHT IDEA
BUT NOT ENOUGH POWER
TO DO IT.
AM I CORRECT IN ASSUMING
THAT A FUSION EXPLOSION
OF 97 MEGATONS
WILL RESULT
IF A STARSHIP
IMPULSE ENGINE
IS OVERLOADED?
NO, SIR.
97.835 MEGATONS.
97.835.
WILL IT BE
POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO DESTROY THAT
THING OUT THERE?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
ITS HULL
IS PURE NEUTRONIUM.
THERE IS NO KNOWN WAY
OF BLASTING THROUGH IT.
NOT THROUGH IT, SPOCK.
FROM INSIDE IT.
WILL IT BE ENOUGH?
INSUFFICIENT DATA.
I SHALL TRY TO TAKE
FURTHER SENSOR READINGS.
DO THE BEST YOU CAN
AND MAKE IT FAST.
KIRK TO SCOTT.
YES, SIR.
THE DAMAGE CONTROL PARTY
JUST BEAMED BACK
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
GOOD. SCOTTY...
CAN YOU SET
THE SHIP'S IMPULSE
ENGINES TO OVERLOAD?
AYE. IN THE SHAPE
THE THING'S IN,
IT'S HARD TO KEEP HER
FROM BLOWING.
I WANT YOU TO RIG
A 30-SECOND DELAY
DETONATION DEVICE
AND RIG IT...
SO THAT
IT CAN BE BLOWN
FROM UP HERE.
AYE, SIR.
SET IT AND GET
UP HERE AS FAST
AS YOU CAN.
RIGHT AWAY.
CAPTAIN?
THE OBJECT'S
NEUTRONIUM HULL
MAKES SENSOR READINGS
OF THE INNER MECHANISM
IMPOSSIBLE.
SPOCK, YOU DON'T KNOW?
CORRECT.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE GETTING
DANGEROUSLY CLOSE
TO THE PLANET KILLER.
I INTEND TO GET
A LOT CLOSER.
I'M GOING TO RAM HER RIGHT
DOWN THAT THING'S THROAT.
JIM...
YOU'LL BE KILLED...
JUST LIKE DECKER.
NO. NO, I DON'T INTEND
TO DIE, MR. SPOCK.
WE'VE RIGGED A DELAY
DETONATION DEVICE.
YOU'LL HAVE 30 SECONDS
TO BEAM ME ABOARD
THE ENTERPRISE
BEFORE
THE CONSTELLATION'S
IMPULSE ENGINES BLOW.
YOUR CHANCES OF SURVIVAL
ARE NOT PROMISING.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF THE EXPLOSION
WILL BE POWERFUL ENOUGH.
A CALCULATED RISK,
MR. SPOCK.
THERE'S ANOTHER FACTOR,
CAPTAIN.
THE TRANSPORTER
IS NOT WORKING
AT 100% EFFICIENCY.
30 SECONDS
IS VERY SLIM TIMING.
A CHANCE
I'LL HAVE TO TAKE.
KIRK OUT.
A CRANKY TRANSPORTER'S
A MIGHTY FINICKY PIECE
OF MACHINERY
TO BE GAMBLING
YOUR LIFE ON, SIR.
WHAT ABOUT
THE DETONATOR?
I'VE LINKED IT IN
WITH THE IMPULSE
CONTROL SYSTEM.
IT'S ARMED NOW.
PRESS THIS ONE--
30 SECONDS LATER...
POOF!
ONCE IT'S ACTIVATED,
THERE'S NO WAY
TO STOP IT.
UNDERSTOOD.
MR. SPOCK.
PREPARE TO BEAM
SCOTTY ONBOARD.
TRANSPORTER,
STAND BY.
GOOD LUCK, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THAT THING?
IT'S A POWER DRAIN
SOMEWHERE, SIR.
I ALMOST LOST YOU.
IT'LL NEVER WORK LIKE THIS.
IT'S THE MAIN JUNCTION
CIRCUITRY.
I'LL GET IT.
BRIDGE. TRANSPORTER
MALFUNCTION.
TRANSPORTER IS OUT,
CAPTAIN. YOU'LL
HAVE TO STAND BY.
I CAN'T. POWER LEVEL'S
DROPPING TOO FAST.
HE'D BETTER HURRY.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
MR. SCOTT, SPEED
IS OF THE ESSENCE.
HE'S 2,000 MILES
FROM THE PLANET KILLER
AND CLOSING FAST.
[CRACKLING]
BRIDGE, TRANSPORTER
OPERATIONAL,
BUT THIS JURY-RIGGING
WON'T LAST FOR LONG.
HE'S GOT TO
COME OFF NOW.
I'LL STAND BY HERE.
1,500 MILES AND CLOSING.
CAPTAIN, TRANSPORTER
OPERATIONAL,
BUT JUST BARELY.
PREPARE TO BEAM ME
ABOARD ON MY SIGNAL.
1,000 MILES AND CLOSING.
TRANSPORTER, STAND BY.
STANDING BY, SIR.
500 MILES AND CLOSING.
BEAM ME ABOARD.
ENERGIZE.
ENERGIZING.
BRIDGE, IT'S
SHORTED OUT AGAIN.
BONKERS.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH IT?
GENTLEMEN...
BEAM ME ABOARD.
WE CAN'T, CAPTAIN.
TRANSPORTER
IS OUT AGAIN.
MR. SCOTT.
20 SECONDS
TO DETONATION.
[SPOCK]
MR. SCOTT.
TRY INVERSE PHASING.
60...
50...
40...
30...
GENTLEMEN,
I SUGGEST YOU
BEAM ME ABOARD.
10...
9...
8...
7...
MR. SCOTT?
6...
TRY HER NOW,
MR. KYLE.
5...4...
[EXPLOSION]
BRIDGE!
WE GOT HIM THROUGH!
ENERGY OUTPUT...
ZERO.
RADIATION LEVEL
NORMAL.
WELCOME ABOARD, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS SHOW
ALL ENERGY SOURCES
DEACTIVATED.
IT'S QUITE DEAD.
MR. SULU...
EASE US BACK
TO MINIMUM HEADWAY.
CONSERVE POWER
AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE.
LIEUTENANT PALMER,
TELL MR. SCOTT
TO EXPEDITE REPAIRS
ON THE WARP DRIVE.
POOR MATT.
HE GAVE HIS LIFE
IN AN ATTEMPT
TO SAVE OTHERS.
NOT THE WORST WAY
TO GO.
INDEED, CAPTAIN.
I PRESUME YOUR LOG
WILL SHOW
THAT COMMODORE DECKER
DIED IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
INDEED IT SHALL,
MR. SPOCK.
IRONIC, ISN'T IT?
WAY BACK
IN THE 20th CENTURY,
THE H-BOMB WAS
THE ULTIMATE WEAPON--
THEIR DOOMSDAY MACHINE.
WE USED SOMETHING LIKE
IT TO DESTROY ANOTHER
DOOMSDAY MACHINE.
PROBABLY THE FIRST TIME
SUCH A WEAPON HAS
EVER BEEN USED FOR
CONSTRUCTIVE PURPOSES.
APPROPRIATE, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, I CAN'T HELP
WONDERING
IF THERE ARE ANY MORE
OF THOSE "WEAPONS"
WANDERING AROUND
THE UNIVERSE.
WELL, I CERTAINLY
HOPE NOT.
I FOUND ONE
QUITE SUFFICIENT.