STILL NO RESPONSE, SIR.
[CLICK]
NO, KEEP IT OPEN.
I DON'T LIKE THIS.
NOTHING SINCE
THE FIRST CHECK-IN.
SCOTT AND SULU SHOULD'VE
CONTACTED US AGAIN
A HALF AN HOUR AGO.
THEY MAY HAVE
NOTHING TO REPORT.
OUR SENSORS INDICATE
NO LIFE FORMS
EXCEPT OUR
LANDING PARTY.
BOTH THOSE MEN
ARE WELL AWARE
OF LANDING PARTY
PROCEDURE.
THEY SHOULD'VE CHECKED
IN WITH US BY NOW.
CONTACT ESTABLISHED,
CAPTAIN.
JACKSON TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
KIRK HERE.
ONE TO BEAM UP,
ENTERPRISE.
ONE?
JACKSON?
WHERE ARE SCOTT
AND SULU?
I'M READY
TO BEAM UP, SIR.
JACKSON!
I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T CLEAR IT, CAPTAIN.
NOTIFY TRANSPORTER ROOM
TO PREPARE TO BEAM UP
ONE MEMBER
OF THE LANDING PARTY.
AND HAVE DR. McCOY REPORT TO
ME IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
ON THE DOUBLE.
YES, SIR.
READY, SIR.
ENERGIZE.
WHAT'S ON, JIM?
TROUBLE.
JACKSON, WHERE ARE
THE OTHERS?
THE MAN IS DEAD.
Male voice:
CAPTAIN KIRK,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
THERE IS A CURSE
ON YOUR SHIP.
LEAVE THIS PLACE,
OR YOU WILL ALL DIE.
Captain Kirk:
SPACE: THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3018.2.
CREWMAN JACKSON IS DEAD,
AND THERE ARE NO
APPARENT PHYSICAL CAUSES.
MR. SCOTT AND MR. SULU
ARE STILL OUT OF TOUCH
ON THE PLANET BELOW.
LEAVING ASSISTANT
CHIEF ENGINEER DeSALLE
IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
I'M BEAMING DOWN
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE
TO FIND MY TWO
MISSING CREWMEN
AND DISCOVER
WHAT KILLED JACKSON.
ODD. OUR PROBE DATA
DIDN'T INDICATE FOG.
NO CLOUD FORMATIONS.
NO BODIES OF WATER.
NO CHANGES
IN SURFACE
TEMPERATURE.
UNDER
THESE CONDITIONS,
FOG IS HIGHLY
UNLIKELY, CAPTAIN.
ACCORDING TO
OUR TRANSPORTER
COORDINATES,
THIS IS THE EXACT
LOCATION
FROM WHICH JACKSON
WAS BEAMED UP
TO THE SHIP.
READINGS, MR. SPOCK.
NO INDICATIONS OF--
A MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
PICKING UP LIFE FORM
READINGS.
"24 DEGREES, MARK 7.
RANGE 137.16 METERS."
MULTIPLE READINGS,
CAPTAIN.
SCOTT AND SULU?
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA HERE.
WHAT ARE
THE SHIP'S SENSORS
READING NOW, LIEUTENANT?
REPORT, MISTER.
I AM ONLY PICKING UP
PHYSICAL IMPULSES
FROM THE THREE OF THEM.
AS FAR AS INSTRUMENTS
CAN MAKE OUT,
THERE IS NOTHING ELSE
DOWN THERE THAT'S ALIVE.
RELAY, LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN, WE ARE ONLY
REGISTERING ON YOU.
[STATIC]
CAPTAIN?
CAPTAIN KIRK?
LIEUTENANT,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
[STATIC]
WHATEVER
THIS STUFF IS,
IT'S GETTING
THICKER.
SUPPOSE THAT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE
INTERFERENCE?
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE HAS TO BE
SOME EXPLANATION
FOR THE FACT
THAT THE SHIP'S SENSORS
CAN'T REGISTER
ANYTHING BUT US,
WHILE WE'RE PICKING UP READINGS
FROM MULTIPLE LIFE FORMS.
ARE THEY STILL THERE,
SPOCK?
NO CHANGE, CAPTAIN.
STANDBY ALERT.
[VOICES WAILING]
LISTEN.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU THINK
THAT--
QUIET.
[VOICES GETTING LOUDER]
CAPTAIN KIRK!
WHO ARE YOU?
GO BACK!
REMEMBER THE CURSE!
WIND SHALL RISE...
AND FOG DESCEND...
SO LEAVE HERE, ALL,
OR MEET YOUR END.
[CACKLING]
SPOCK.
COMMENT.
VERY BAD POETRY,
CAPTAIN.
A MORE USEFUL COMMENT,
MR. SPOCK.
WHAT WE'VE JUST SEEN
IS NOT REAL.
THAT'S USEFUL.
HOWEVER, ON ASMET 24,
AT JUST OVER 100 METERS,
THERE ARE DEFINITELY
LIFE FORMS.
ERRATIC, CONFUSED,
BUT DEFINITELY
REGISTERING.
THAT'S WHERE WE GO.
THAT WAS A PRETTY REAL
ILLUSION, MR. SPOCK.
JIM.
THIS IS THE SOURCE
OF THE LIFE FORM
READINGS, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE INSIDE.
SOMEWHERE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
IS THIS HOW
WE LOST CONTACT
WITH THE FIRST
LANDING PARTY?
WHAT ABOUT IT, SPOCK?
DOES THIS STRUCTURE
HAVE ANYTHING TO DO WITH
COMMUNICATOR INTERFERENCE?
I WOULD SAY NOT,
CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NO INDICATION
OF ANYTHING
THAT WOULD CAUSE
SUCH INTERFERENCE.
AND IT DOESN'T PICK UP
ON OUR SHIP'S SENSORS.
NOR DO
OUR SENSORS REGISTER
THE LIFE FORMS INSIDE.
COULD BE EXERTING
A FORCE FIELD OF SOME KIND
THAT CUTS INTO OUR
SENSOR SCAN.
THEN IT WOULD
AFFECT SPOCK'S
TRICORDER, TOO.
WOULDN'T IT?
WOULD IT?
I WONDER.
[GRRR]
[MEOW]
THREE WITCHES...
WHAT APPEARS TO BE A CASTLE
AND A BLACK CAT.
IF WE WEREN'T
MISSING TWO OFFICERS
AND A THIRD ONE
DEAD,
I'D SAY SOMEONE
WAS PLAYING
AN ELABORATE TRICK
OR TREAT ON US.
TRICK OR TREAT,
CAPTAIN?
YES, MR. SPOCK.
YOU'D BE A NATURAL.
I'LL EXPLAIN IT
TO YOU ONE DAY.
SHALL WE HAVE
A LOOK AROUND?
THAT WOULD SEEM
TO BE IN ORDER.
BONES, SPOCK.
THEY'RE GONE,
MR. DeSALLE.
THE CAPTAIN
AND THE OTHERS...
SIMPLY STOPPED
REGISTERING.
CHECK FOR MALFUNCTIONS.
I DID, SIR,
AS SOON AS IT HAPPENED.
MR. DeSALLE, THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
TO MR. SCOTT
AND HIS PARTY.
THEY...
THEY JUST DISAPPEARED.
NOBODY
JUST DISAPPEARS.
THEY MAY HAVE
ENCOUNTERED
A MAGNETIC FIELD
OR SOME OTHER
OBSTRUCTION.
MR. CHEKOV,
RECALIBRATE
YOUR SENSORS.
IF YOU
NEED HELP--
I CAN DO IT, SIR.
I'M NOT THAT GREEN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTINUE IN YOUR EFFORTS
TO BREAK THROUGH THAT
STATIC INTERFERENCE.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
WE KNOW
THEY'RE DOWN THERE.
I WANT THEM FOUND.
[SLAM]
STRAIGHT AHEAD,
MR. SPOCK?
THE READINGS
WOULD SO INDICATE.
DUST, COBWEBS...
HALLOWEEN
IS RIGHT.
[MEOW]
SPOCK.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
I AM UNDAMAGED,
CAPTAIN.
BONES?
DOC?
YOU WERE SAYING
SOMETHING ABOUT
TRICK OR TREAT.
DUNGEONS...
CURSES...
SKELETONS
AND IRON MAIDENS...
THEY'RE ALL
EARTH MANIFESTATIONS.
WHY?
I DO NOT KNOW,
CAPTAIN,
BUT THESE THINGS
DO EXIST.
THEY ARE...
REAL.
COULD THIS BE
AN EARTH PARALLEL
DEVELOPMENT
OF SOME SORT?
NONE OF THIS PARALLELS
ANY HUMAN DEVELOPMENT.
IT'S MORE LIKE
A HUMAN NIGHTMARE.
AS IF SOMEONE
KNEW WHAT IT WAS
THAT TERRIFIES MAN MOST
ON AN INSTINCTIVE LEVEL.
GHOST STORIES...
OGRES, DEMONS...
ALL...
[DOOR UNLOCKS]
SCOTTY, SULU...
SCOTTY.
PUT DOWN THE PHASER.
THEY APPEAR
TO BE DRUGGED, JIM.
LOOK AT THEIR EYES.
HARDLY BLINK AT ALL.
NEITHER DID JACKSON
JUST BEFORE HE COLLAPSED.
THESE TWO ARE ALIVE.
SCOTTY, DO YOU HEAR ME?
SULU, DO YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU?
HEY, I THINK THEY'RE
GOING TO RELEASE US.
STOP!
WHOEVER YOU ARE,
YOU'VE PROVEN YOUR SKILL
AT CREATING ILLUSION.
NOW I WANT TO KNOW WHY
AND WHAT YOU'VE DONE
TO MY MEN.
WHERE DID YOUR RACE
GET THIS RIDICULOUS
PREDILECTION
FOR RESISTANCE, HMM?
YOU EXAMINE ANY OBJECT.
YOU QUESTION EVERYTHING.
IS IT NOT ENOUGH
TO ACCEPT WHAT IS?
NOT WHEN ONE
OF MY MEN IS DEAD
BECAUSE OF IT
AND TWO OTHERS
TURNED INTO MINDLESS--
NOT MINDLESS.
THESE TWO ARE
MERELY CONTROLLED,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
OH, YES, WE KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
ALL OF YOU.
DON'T WE, MY PRECIOUS,
HMM?
[MEOW]
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY DID YOU
BRING US HERE?
MY NAME IS KOROB.
AND AS FOR
BRINGING YOU HERE,
IT WAS YOU
WHO QUITE CONTRARILY
INSISTED UPON COMING.
YOU WERE WARNED
TO STAY AWAY.
BUT WHY?
FOR WHAT REASON?
WHY ALL THE MUMBO-JUMBO?
MUMBO-JUMBO?
[MEOW]
OH!
OH, NO, I ASSURE YOU
IT WAS NOT THAT, CAPTAIN.
MAPPING EXPEDITIONS
HAVE CHARTED THIS
SOLAR SYSTEM BEFORE.
THERE NEVER HAVE
BEEN ANY LIFE FORMS
ON PYRUS 7.
IT IS OF NO IMPORTANCE
THAT WE ARE NOT
NATIVE TO THIS PLANET.
[MEOW]
OH! I'M--I'M TOLD
THAT I'VE BEEN
AN INATTENTIVE HOST,
GENTLEMEN.
YOU WILL JOIN ME
FOR SOMETHING
TO REFRESH YOURSELVES.
THAT CAT.
HMM.
THERE ARE ANCIENT
EARTH LEGENDS
ABOUT WIZARDS
AND THEIR FAMILIARS.
FAMILIARS?
DEMONS
IN ANIMAL FORMS
SENT BY SATAN
TO SERVE THE WIZARD.
SUPERSTITION.
I DO NOT CREATE
THE LEGEND, CAPTAIN.
I MERELY REPORT IT.
YOU ARE THE, UH...
DIFFERENT ONE, MR. SPOCK.
YOU DO NOT THINK
LIKE THE OTHERS.
THERE ARE NO COLORS
TO YOUR PATTERNS OF LOGIC.
THERE'S ONLY
BLACK AND WHITE.
YOU SEE ALL THIS
AROUND YOU,
AND YET YOU DO NOT BELIEVE.
HE DOESN'T KNOW
ABOUT TRICK OR TREAT.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND
THAT REFERENCE,
THEREFORE IT ALSO
IS OF NO IMPORTANCE.
GENTLEMEN...
I CAN BE MOST
HOSPITABLE.
INGENIOUS.
DO BE SEATED.
WE'RE NOT HUNGRY.
BUT I INSIST.
[MEOW]
Captain Kirk:
ALL RIGHT, KOROB.
WHAT DO
YOU WANT FROM US?
FOR THE MOMENT,
MERELY THAT YOU
EAT AND ENJOY YOURSELVES.
OH, DOCTOR,
DO TRY THE WINE.
YOU'LL FIND IT
EXCELLENT.
YOU'LL FIND US
MOST UNCOOPERATIVE,
UNLESS YOU START
EXPLAINING YOURSELF.
HOPEFULLY I CAN
CHANGE THAT ATTITUDE.
THESE LOOK REAL.
OH, THEY ARE,
I ASSURE YOU.
DIAMONDS, RUBIES,
EMERALDS, SAPPHIRES--
ALL THE CRYSTALLINE FORMS
THAT YOU CHERISH
ABOVE ALL THINGS.
A FORTUNE OF THEM
FOR EACH OF YOU,
IF YOU LEAVE HERE
WITHOUT FURTHER INQUIRY.
WE COULD MANUFACTURE
A TON OF THESE ON OUR
SHIP FOR YOU, KOROB.
THEY MEAN NOTHING
TO US.
VALUELESS?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I READ--
WHATEVER IT IS
YOU READ,
YOU READ IT WRONG.
AS FOR LEAVING,
WE'LL LEAVE
WHEN WE'RE READY.
YOU ARE MOST, UM...
UNPREDICTABLE.
HMM!
PERHAPS I HAVE MADE
A SMALL MISTAKE.
NEVERTHELESS,
YOU HAVE PASSED
THE TESTS.
TESTS?
YES. OUR ANALYSIS
OF YOU
MAY HAVE BEEN
IN SOME SMALL WAY
IN ERROR,
BUT YOU WERE WARNED
TO STAY AWAY,
AND YET YOU CAME
TO SAVE YOUR COMRADES.
THAT PROVES LOYALTY.
YOUR BRAVERY WAS TESTED,
AND YOU DID NOT
FRIGHTEN.
AND DESPITE MY FAILURE
WITH THESE BRIGHT BAUBLES,
I PERCEIVE THAT
YOU CANNOT BE BRIBED.
IN MANY WAYS
YOU ARE QUITE ADMIRABLE.
[MEOW]
HMM?
OH, QUITE RIGHT.
GO AT ONCE, YES.
GENTLEMEN,
MY COLLEAGUE SYLVIA.
DR. McCOY...
MR. SPOCK...
AND CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU WANTED TO KNOW
WHAT WE DID TO YOUR MEN.
ACTUALLY IT'S
A SIMPLE MATTER FOR US
TO PROBE THE MINDS
OF CREATURES LIKE YOURSELF.
MIND PROBING?
HYPNOSIS?
YOU LIKE
TO THINK OF YOURSELVES
AS COMPLEX CREATURES,
BUT YOU'RE FLAWED.
ONE GAINS
ADMITTANCE TO YOUR MINDS
THROUGH MANY LEVELS.
YOU HAVE TOO MANY
TO KEEP TRACK OF YOURSELVES.
THERE ARE
UNGUARDED ENTRANCES
TO ANY HUMAN MIND.
TELEPATHY.
NOT ENTIRELY.
NO, TELEPATHY
DOESN'T IMPLY CONTROL,
AND I ASSURE YOU THAT
I HAVE FULL CONTROL
OVER YOUR FRIENDS.
DON'T MOVE!
COVER THEM.
NOW, I WANT THE REST
OF OUR WEAPONS
AND OUR EQUIPMENT.
I WANT SOME ANSWERS.
PUT THAT WEAPON DOWN!
CAPTAIN, IT SEEMS
SO FOOLISH OF YOU
TO INSIST
ON DEMONSTRATIONS.
IN THE MYTHOLOGY
OF YOUR RACE,
THIS IS CALLED
SYMPATHETIC MAGIC.
JACKSON,
THE CREW MEMBER WHO
RETURNED TO THE SHIP,
YOU WONDERED
WHAT KILLED HIM.
I MADE AN IMAGE OF HIM.
IN THE ESSENCE
OF MY THOUGHTS,
THE IMAGE WAS JACKSON.
AND WHEN I KILLED
THE IMAGE
AND KNEW
THAT IT WAS DEAD,
HE DIED.
YOU CAN'T
THINK A MAN TO DEATH.
YOUR COMMUNICATOR.
NOW...
SIGNAL YOUR SHIP.
DON'T.
SYLVIA, DON'T.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
ENTERPRISE.
FROM CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN.
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHERE ARE YOU?
ARE THE OTHERS
ALL RIGHT, SIR?
NEVER MIND ABOUT US.
WHAT'S HAPPENING UP THERE?
THE TEMPERATURE, SIR--
KEEPS RISING.
READING, MISTER.
IT'S OVER 60 DEGREES
IN THE PAST 30 SECONDS.
WE'RE BURNING UP, SIR.
DeSALLE...
CHANNEL BYPASS POWER
INTO YOUR HEAT
DISSIPATION UNITS.
WE'VE ALREADY DONE IT,
CAPTAIN.
IT HAD NO EFFECT.
WE'RE COOKING UP HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL HANDLE IT DOWN HERE.
KIRK OUT.
YOU'VE WON.
HEE HEE!
YOU CAN RELAX NOW,
CAPTAIN.
YOUR SHIP IS SAFE.
TEMPERATURE IS ALMOST
BACK TO NORMAL--
DROPPING DOWN FAST.
LIEUTENANT, TRY TO RAISE
THE CAPTAIN AGAIN.
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, PLEASE.
[STATIC]
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
[STATIC]
WE'VE LOST HIM AGAIN,
MR. DeSALLE.
CAPTAIN, YOU'VE SEEN
SOMETHING OF OUR SCIENCE,
NOW--NOW TELL US
ABOUT YOURS.
YOU SEEM TO BE SINGING
A DIFFERENT TUNE.
I'D RATHER KNOW
MORE ABOUT YOURS.
YOU CALL IT MAGIC,
YOU CALL IT SCIENCE.
IT SEEMS TO BE UNRELATED
TO BOTH OF THEM.
WHAT WOULD YOU NAME IT?
I WOULDN'T ATTEMPT
AT NAMING IT.
YOU SEEM TO DO
WITH YOUR MIND
WHAT WE DO WITH TOOLS.
YOU ALTER MATTER--
MOVE IT ABOUT
BY TELEKINESIS.
YES, WE CAN CHANGE
THE MOLECULAR STRUCT--
KOROB,
YOU TALK TOO MUCH.
YOU KEPT SCOTT AND SULU
AS CAT'S-PAWS
TO LURE US DOWN HERE.
HOW'D YOU KNOW
WE'D COME?
OH, WE DIDN'T
HAVE TO KNOW.
THEY KNEW.
ENOUGH OF THIS!
YOU WILL TELL US
WHAT WE WANT TO KNOW.
IT'S TOO LATE
FOR THREATS.
YOU LET ME
CONTACT THE SHIP.
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
IT WILL BE BEFORE
A SEARCH PARTY ARRIVES?
SOME TIME, CAPTAIN.
QUITE SOME TIME.
THERE WILL
BE NO SEARCH PARTY,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
AN IMPENETRABLE
FORCE FIELD
AROUND YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN.
IT WILL NOT HINDER ORBIT,
BUT YOUR PEOPLE
ARE PRISONERS WITHIN IT.
IT'S SOME KIND
OF A FORCE FIELD, SIR...
BUT NOT LIKE ANY OTHER
I'VE EVER HEARD OF BEFORE.
IT'S NOT COMING
FROM ANYWHERE.
IT'S SIMPLY
ALL AROUND US.
I WOULD ADVISE YOU
TO COOPERATE, CAPTAIN.
FORCIBLE EXTRACTION
OF THE INFORMATION
WE WISH FROM YOU
IS NOT COMPLICATED,
BUT IT IS
EXTREMELY PAINFUL,
AND IT HAS A CERTAIN
DRAINING EFFECT.
WE HAVE NOTHING
TO DISCUSS.
TAKE THEM TO THEIR CELL.
WAIT.
THE DOCTOR WILL STAY.
YOU'RE TURN WILL BE
NEXT, CAPTAIN. IT MAKES
LITTLE DIFFERENCE.
TAKE THEM
OUT OF HERE.
WAVELENGTH ANALYSIS,
MR. CHEKOV.
IT WILL NOT ANALYZE,
SIR.
ALL RIGHT...
BUT IT'S THERE,
AND IT'S REAL.
IF IT'S REAL,
IT CAN BE AFFECTED.
ENGINEERING,
STAND BY TO DIVERT
ALL POWER SYSTEMS
TO THE OUTER HULL.
PREPARE IMPULSE ENGINES
FOR GENERATION
OF MAXIMUM HEAT
DIRECTED AS ORDERED.
MAYBE WE CAN'T BREAK IT,
BUT I'LL BET YOU
CREDITS TO NAVY BEANS
WE CAN PUT A DENT
IN IT.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
22 MINUTES, 17 SECONDS.
THANKS.
I WONDER WHAT
THEY'RE DOING TO DOC.
I'M SURE
WE'LL FIND OUT SHORTLY.
JIM...
ALL THESE THINGS
THAT WE'VE SEEN--
TO AN EARTHMAN
LIKE YOURSELF,
THEY MUST SEEM
QUITE FAMILIAR.
TO ME?
STARTLING...
NOT RATIONAL.
PRECISELY.
I REFER YOU TO
THE PSYCHOLOGICAL THEORY
OF THE RACIAL SUBCONSCIOUS.
THE UNIVERSAL MYTHS,
SYMBOLS--
GHOSTS, WITCHES.
AND DUNGEONS AND CASTLES
AND BLACK CATS.
THEY ALL BELONG
TO THE TWILIGHT WORLD
OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
THEY TRIED TO TAP
OUR CONSCIOUS MIND.
AND THEY MISSED.
THEY REACHED BASICALLY
ONLY THE SUBCONSCIOUS.
KOROB SEEMED QUITE PUZZLED
BY YOUR REACTION
TO THE ENVIRONMENT
HE'D PROVIDED.
HE EXPECTED ME TO REACT
AS THOUGH
IT WERE ALL NORMAL.
WELL, HE ADMITTED
THAT THEY WEREN'T
NATIVE TO THIS PLANET.
AND NOT TO HAVE A KNOWLEDGE
OF OUR SCIENTIFIC METHODS
IS MOST UNLIKELY
FOR ANY LIFE FORM
WE'VE MET IN THIS GALAXY.
THEY REFER TO US
AS CREATURES,
AS THOUGH WE WERE
SOME SPECIES
THAT THEY WERE
UNFAMILIAR WITH.
WELL, IF WE'RE
CREATURES...
I WONDER WHAT
THEY'RE REALLY LIKE.
EVIDENTLY SOMETHING
TOTALLY ALIEN
IN ALL RESPECTS.
AGREED.
TOTALLY ALIEN.
AND I DON'T LIKE
HOSTILE STRANGERS
SHOWING SUCH
AN ACUTE INTEREST
IN OUR GALAXY,
OUR WORLD, SPOCK.
NOT AT ALL
LIKE FRIENDLY VISITORS.
WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO STOP THEM COLD.
BUT AT THE MOMENT...
I, TOO, AM AT A LOSS
AT THIS TIME
TO SUGGEST
A COURSE OF ACTION.
[DOOR OPENS]
OH, BONES.
DOC.
YOU FORGET WHAT WE
WERE SENT HERE FOR.
I FORGET NOTHING.
I'M NOT A PUPPET,
KOROB, LIKE YOU.
YOU'RE A TRAITOR.
YOU ARE A FOOL.
WE HAVE
NOTHING LIKE THIS,
AND I LIKE IT.
TO TOUCH, TO FEEL,
TO UNDERSTAND
THE IDEA OF LUXURY--
I LIKE IT.
AND I DON'T INTEND
TO LEAVE IT.
WE HAVE A DUTY
TO THE OLD ONES.
WHAT DO THEY KNOW
OF SENSATIONS?
THIS IS A NEW WORLD.
YOU'RE CRUEL.
YOU TORTURE
OUR SPECIMENS.
AND THAT, TOO,
IS A NEW SENSATION.
I FIND IT STIMULATING.
YOU'RE WRONG!
YOU'RE DISCARDING
EVERYTHING WE LIVE BY.
I LIVE BY
MY OWN DECISIONS.
YOU'RE A WEAK FOOL, KOROB.
I HAVE THE POWER.
BUT YOU'RE AFRAID
TO USE IT.
DON'T THREATEN ME.
I CAN SQUASH YOU,
AND THAT WOULD BE
AN INTERESTING SENSATION, YES.
I FIND I LIKE
THESE NEW SENSATIONS.
DON'T TRY TO PUSH ME.
OH, CAPTAIN.
IT'S TIME FOR OUR TALK.
KOROB, LEAVE US ALONE,
AND TAKE THESE MEN
WITH YOU.
THIS IS NOT ENDED,
SYLVIA.
BUT IT MAY END SOON,
OLD MAN.
WHAT NOW?
YOU WAVE YOUR MAGIC WAND
AND DESTROY MY MIND, TOO?
THERE'S NO REAL DAMAGE
TO THE MIND, CAPTAIN,
SIMPLY A DRAIN
OF KNOWLEDGE AND WILL.
YOU DON'T
CALL THAT DAMAGE?
WHY SHOULD I?
YOU'D KNOW...
IF YOU HAD COMPASSION.
A WOMAN
SHOULD HAVE COMPASSION,
BUT I FORGET
YOU'RE NOT A WOMAN.
BUT YOU'RE MISTAKEN,
CAPTAIN.
I AM A WOMAN NOW.
I COME FROM A WORLD
WITHOUT SENSATION,
AS YOU AND I NOW KNOW IT.
IT EXCITES ME.
I WANT MORE.
YOU SEEM TO NEED US.
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
KNOWLEDGE WHICH I LACK,
BUT WERE OUR ABILITIES
PUT TOGETHER...
TELL ME ABOUT POWER,
CAPTAIN.
HOW DOES IT FEEL?
WHAT ABOUT KOROB?
HE IS A FOOL.
I'LL DO WITHOUT HIM,
BUT YOU--
WHY DO I
FIND YOU DIFFERENT?
WHY WOULD IT
BE SO DIFFICULT
TO DISPOSE OF YOU?
WHY DON'T YOU SIMPLY
PROBE MY MIND
AND GET WHAT YOU WANT?
NO, NOT THAT,
NOT FOR YOU.
WHAT I WANT IS...
IS A JOINING--
MY MIND TO YOURS
WILLINGLY.
THINK OF THE SECRETS
YOU WOULD LEARN.
THINK OF THE POWER
THAT WOULD BE YOURS.
ANYTHING YOU CAN IMAGINE,
I CAN GIVE YOU.
YOU'RE VERY PERSUASIVE.
WHAT HAPPENS
IF I GO ALONG?
THEN EVERYTHING
WOULD BE OURS TOGETHER.
I'VE NEVER
CONCEIVED OF THE IDEA
OF TOGETHERNESS BEFORE.
IT EXCITES ME.
YOU EXCITE ME.
WHY?
FOR THE SAME REASONS
YOU EXCITE ME.
YOU'RE
A VERY BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
YOU FIND ME BEAUTIFUL?
BUT I CAN BE
MANY WOMEN.
YOU LIKE WHAT YOU SEE...
OR DO YOU PREFER ME
AS I WAS?
YOU HAVE A KNACK
FOR GIVING ME
DIFFICULT CHOICES.
YOU HAVE
NOTHING LIKE THAT
WHERE YOU COME FROM?
NOTHING.
YOUR PEOPLE...
WHEN THEY COME HERE...
THEY'RE LIKE...
LIKE FEATHERS IN THE WIND
WITHOUT THE TRANSMUTER.
TRANSMUTER?
THE SOURCE.
YOU WILL LEARN.
I WILL TEACH YOU LATER--
LATER.
THEN IT'S A DEVICE.
YOU DO USE TOOLS.
OH, IT GIVES ONLY FORM.
YOU'RE TEACHING ME
SUBSTANCE.
YOU HAVEN'T
CHANGED YOUR MIND?
YOU WON'T RETURN HOME?
MY HOME
IS HERE WITH YOU--
A BILLION WORLDS
OF SENSATION
TO PICK AND CHOOSE.
YOU ARE USING ME.
YOU HOLD ME IN YOUR ARMS,
AND THERE IS NO FIRE
IN YOUR MIND.
YOU'RE TRYING
TO DECEIVE ME!
IT'S HERE
LIKE WORDS ON A PAGE.
YOU ARE USING ME.
AND WHY NOT?
YOU'VE BEEN USING
ME AND MY CREW.
[DOOR OPENS]
YOU WILL BE SWEPT AWAY--
YOU, YOUR MEN, YOUR SHIP,
YOUR WORLDS!
I DON'T SEE ANY CHANGE.
IT'S THERE,
LIEUTENANT.
IT WAS
THAT ELECTRICAL FIELD
WE SET UP, MR. DeSALLE,
THAT DENT YOU WANTED.
IT'S NOT MUCH,
BUT IT IS A START.
KEEP IT UP,
MR. CHEKOV.
CHANNEL
THE ENTIRE OUTPUT
OF REACTORS
1, 2, AND 3
INTO
THE RELAY STATIONS.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT'S STARTING
TO WEAKEN.
I'VE RELEASED
THE MODEL OF YOUR SHIP
FROM THE CRYSTAL,
ALTHOUGH THEY WOULD HAVE
FREED THEMSELVES SOON.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO CONTROL
SO MANY THINGS
IN SO LITTLE TIME.
HERE.
YOU MUST GO
BEFORE SHE FINDS
THE WEAPON IS MISSING.
I'M NOT LEAVING
WITHOUT MY MEN.
THEY'RE NOT
YOUR MEN ANYMORE.
THEY BELONG TO SYLVIA.
I CAN NO LONGER
CONTROL THEM...
OR HER.
SHE'S IRRATIONAL--
THE STRAIN OF ADOPTING
TO YOUR FORM,
THE INSATIABLE DESIRE
FOR SENSATION
AND EXPERIENCE.
SHE'S A GREAT DANGER,
AND IT
WAS NOT NECESSARY.
WE COULD HAVE ENTERED
YOUR GALAXY IN PEACE.
YOU CAME IN A SHIP?
WE USED THE TRANSMUTER.
TRANSMUTER, YES.
SHE MENTIONED THAT.
THERE'S NO TIME
TO EXPLAIN NOW.
SHE MEANS
TO DESTROY US ALL.
THERE MIGHT STILL
BE A CHANCE.
QUICKLY.
COME.
[GRRR]
FASCINATING.
WHY A CAT?
RACIAL MEMORIES.
THE CAT IS
THE MOST RUTHLESS,
MOST TERRIFYING
OF ANIMALS,
AS FAR BACK AS
THE SABER-TOOTHED TIGER.
I THINK
I CAN STOP HER.
YOU BETTER LET US.
IT'S OUT OF ENERGY.
SHE MUST HAVE DRAINED IT.
WE COULD HAVE JUMPED
SCOTT AND SULU
AT ANY TIME.
WE DIDN'T KNOW.
NO WAY OUT.
IT'S MY PROBLEM.
SHE'S ONE OF MY KIND.
COME QUICKLY.
[GRRR]
DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN MAKE IT?
READY WHEN YOU ARE,
CAPTAIN.
GET READY.
[GRRR]
NO!
GET BACK.
GET BACK!
KOROB,
THAT DOOR WON'T LAST.
GET BACK!
GO.
GO!
[GRRR]
QUICKLY, CAPTAIN.
KOROB SEEMED TO THINK
THIS WAS IMPORTANT.
SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT A TRANSMUTER.
CAPTAIN,
A BIT MORE ALACRITY,
IF YOU PLEASE.
CAPTAIN.
DOC.
AHA!
JIM!
WELL, AT LEAST
WE FOUND THEM.
FORTUITOUS, CAPTAIN.
AND NOW THAT WE HAVE
THEM ALL TOGETHER?
[GRRR]
MOST UNPLEASANT
SITUATION, CAPTAIN.
IF ONLY YOUR PHASER
HAD SOME POWER.
[GRRR]
MAYBE WE DO.
SYLVIA...
I HAVE THE TRANSMUTER.
IT'S MINE NOW.
[GRRR]
YOU'RE VERY CLEVER,
CAPTAIN--
MORE SO THAN I'D IMAGINED.
CLEVER...
RESOURCEFUL...
AND HANDSOME.
DON'T LET HER
TOUCH THE WAND, CAPTAIN.
JIM!
DON'T YOU GET TIRED
OF THESE GAMES?
I'VE NEVER PLAYED GAMES.
GIVE IT TO ME.
I WASN'T SURE BEFORE,
BUT I AM NOW.
THIS IS THE SOURCE
OF YOUR POWER, ISN'T IT?
THE TRANSMUTER?
NO, NOT THE SOURCE.
IT'S MERELY AN AMPLIFIER.
A DIRECT TO THE MIND
IS THE SOURCE.
MINE IS SIMPLE,
BUT YOURS HAS THE KEY,
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW TO USE IT.
I CATCH ON QUICKLY.
IT IS NOT TOO LATE,
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
COME WITH ME.
I WILL TEACH YOU.
YOU WILL TEACH ME.
WHY? BECAUSE YOUR
PEOPLE HAVE NOTHING
OF YOUR OWN?
IS THAT WHY YOU NEED US?
WE NEED YOUR DREAMS,
YOUR AMBITION.
WITH THEM I CAN BUILD.
GIVE ME THE TRANSMUTER.
NO.
YOU FOOL.
DON'T YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE GIVING UP?
EVERYTHING
THAT YOUR SPECIES
FINDS DESIRABLE.
LOOK AT ME.
I AM A WOMAN.
I AM ALL WOMEN.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU ARE,
BUT YOU'RE NOT A WOMAN.
YOU'VE TORTURED MY MEN
AND TAKEN THEIR MINDS
FROM THEM.
YOU ASK FOR LOVE
AND RETURN PAIN INSTEAD.
KOROB WAS WRONG.
I DIDN'T DESTROY
ALL YOUR WEAPONS.
GIVE ME THE TRANSMUTER.
GIVE IT TO ME!
WHAT HAPPENED, JIM?
THAT'LL TAKE
SOME EXPLAINING, BONES.
EVERYTHING'S VANISHED.
NOT EVERYTHING.
KOROB AND SYLVIA
AS THEY REALLY ARE.
THEIR FORMS
WERE AN ILLUSION,
JUST LIKE THE CASTLE
AND EVERYTHING ELSE.
ONLY THE POWER PACK
GAVE THEM REALITY.
FASCINATING.
A LIFE FORM
TOTALLY ALIEN
TO OUR GALAXY.
IF WE COULD PRESERVE
AND STUDY THIS...
TOO LATE.
ALL OF THIS,
JUST AN ILLUSION.
NO ILLUSION.
JACKSON IS DEAD.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
Uhura:
STANDING BY, CAPTAIN.
FIVE TO BEAM UP.