MORNING, SIR,
DOCTOR.
SOMETHING WRONG?
YES. THERE'S SOMETHING ODD
ABOUT THAT MAN,
AND I CAN'T QUITE
PINPOINT IT.
PERHAPS YOU'RE MAKING
A RATHER HASTY JUDGMENT.
MR. NORMAN HAS ONLY
BEEN ABOARD 72 HOURS.
WELL, I KNOW WHEN SOMETHING
DOESN'T STRIKE ME RIGHT,
AND HE DOESN'T.
SPECIFICS, DOCTOR.
LABELS DO NOT
MAKE ARGUMENTS.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S SOMETHING
WRONG ABOUT A MAN
WHO NEVER SMILES,
WHOSE CONVERSATION
NEVER VARIES
FROM THE ROUTINE
OF THE JOB,
AND WHO WON'T TALK
ABOUT HIS BACKGROUND.
I SEE.
SPOCK, I MEAN THAT IT'S
ODD FOR A NON-VULCAN.
THE EARS MAKE ALL
OF THE DIFFERENCE.
I FIND YOUR ARGUMENT
STREWN
WITH GAPING DEFECTS
IN LOGIC.
MAYBE, BUT YOU CAN'T
EVALUATE A MAN
BY LOGIC ALONE.
BESIDES, HE HAS AVOIDED
TWO APPOINTMENTS
THAT I'VE MADE
FOR HIS PHYSICAL EXAM
WITHOUT REASON.
THAT'S NOT AT ALL
SURPRISING, DOCTOR.
HE'S PROBABLY
TERRIFIED
OF YOUR BEADS
AND RATTLES.
COMMAND PERSONNEL ONLY.
YES, MR. SULU?
THERE'S AN UNPLANNED
COURSE CHANGE
BEING FED INTO
THE INSTRUMENTS, SIR.
CORRECT IT.
I CAN'T, SIR.
AUXILIARY CONTROL,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S GOING ON
DOWN THERE?
SIR, AUXILIARY CONTROL
IS ON TOTAL OVERRIDE.
KIRK TO SECURITY.
SECURITY. LIEUTENANT
ROWE HERE, SIR.
INTRUDER ALERT--
DECK EIGHT,
AUXILIARY CONTROL.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HAVE MR. SPOCK REPORT
TO THE BRIDGE.
AYE, SIR.
WHAT'S THE IMPOSED COURSE,
MR. SULU?
TURNING ON
307 DEGREES, MARK 8.
BEING EXECUTED
NOW, SIR.
TAKE CARE OF HIM.
SECURITY TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
LIEUTENANT ROWE, SIR.
I'M IN AUXILIARY CONTROL.
ENSIGN JORDAN'S
BEEN KNOCKED OUT.
THE DIRECTIONAL
MASTER CONTROLS
HAVE BEEN JAMMED.
THEY'RE TOTALLY UNWORKABLE.
ANY SIGN OF
THE INTRUDER?
NO, SIR. HE'S GONE.
I'VE PUT OUT A FULL
SECURITY ALERT
ON ALL DECKS.
FIND HIM. KIRK OUT.
MR. SPOCK, WE SEEM TO BE
TAKING AN UNSCHEDULED RIDE.
INTERESTING.
MR. SULU, CUT AN EMERGENCY
MANUAL MONITOR.
I WANT
THE OVERRIDE BROKEN.
SIR, THE INSTRUMENTS
WON'T RESPOND.
EMERGENCY MANUAL MONITOR,
REPORT.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
EMERGENCY MANUAL MONITOR,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
REPORT.
HERE, YOU'RE
NOT ALLOWED--
ACKNOWLEDGE.
THIS IS THE
CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY,
ACKNOWLEDGE.
WHAT'S GOING ON
DOWN THERE?
KIRK TO ENGINEERING.
THIS IS THE
CAPTAIN. SCOTTY,
REPORT.
SCOTTY, THE INTRUDER'S
IN YOUR AREA.
WHAT'S GOING ON
DOWN THERE? SCOTTY?
CAPTAIN, HE'S HERE.
SCOTTY!
SCOTTY?
SECURITY, THE INTRUDER'S
IN THE ENGINEERING SECTION.
HAVE ALL UNITS
CONVERGE ON THAT POINT.
SIR, WE'RE PICKING UP
SPEED. WARP 5...6...
WARP 7, SIR.
CUT POWER.
I CAN'T, SIR.
ALL THE CONTROLS
ARE JAMMED.
SPOCK, TAKE OVER.
IT WILL NOT
BE NECESSARY,
CAPTAIN.
TELL SECURITY
WE'VE FOUND THE INTRUDER.
YOU MIND TELLING ME WHAT
THIS IS ALL ABOUT, MISTER?
I AM IN TOTAL CONTROL
OF YOUR SHIP.
I HAVE CONNECTED THE
MATTER-ANTIMATTER PODS
TO THE MAIN
NAVIGATIONAL BANK.
A TRIGGER RELAY
IS NOW IN OPERATION.
ANY ATTEMPTS
TO ALTER COURSE
WILL RESULT IN THE
IMMEDIATE DESTRUCTION
OF THIS VESSEL.
SPOCK?
CONFIRMED, CAPTAIN.
HE'S TAKEN OUT
ALL THE OVERRIDE CONTROLS.
IF WE TAMPER WITHOUT KNOWING
WHERE THE TRIGGER RELAY IS,
WE COULD
EXTINGUISH OURSELVES.
WHO ARE YOU?
I ASSURE YOU,
WE ARE NO THREAT
TO HUMANITY
OR HUMANOID LIFE.
WE MEAN YOU NO HARM,
BUT WE REQUIRE
YOUR SHIP.
YOU REQUIRE--
WHO AND WHAT
ARE "WE"?
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
AN ANDROID.
AND MOST SOPHISTICATED.
I CONTROL
THE TRIGGER RELAY, SIR.
I CANNOT BE OVERCOME
BY PHYSICAL MEANS,
AND IF YOU ATTEMPT
TO USE YOUR PHASERS,
THE TRIGGER RELAY
WILL BE ACTIVATED.
WE SHALL CONTINUE ON
OUR PRESENT COURSE
FOR APPROXIMATELY
4 SOLAR DAYS,
AT WHICH TIME
WE SHALL ARRIVE
AT OUR DESTINATION.
WHO SENT YOU?
I AM NOT PROGRAMMED
TO RESPOND IN THAT AREA.
HE APPEARS TO HAVE
TURNED HIMSELF OFF,
CAPTAIN.
AND SINCE WE CANNOT
REPAIR THE DAMAGE
HE HAS DONE
WITHOUT DESTROYING
THE SHIP--
IT SEEMS WE'RE GOING
TO TAKE A LITTLE TRIP.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 4513.3.
AFTER HAVING BEEN
TAKEN OVER BY AN ANDROID,
THE "ENTERPRISE"
HAS BEEN UNDERWAY AT WARP 7
FOR 4 DAYS.
NOW WE ARE ENTERING ORBIT
AROUND A PLANET
WHICH HAS NEVER BEEN CHARTED.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
THE FOLLOWING
INDIVIDUALS
WILL BE TRANSPORTED
DOWN TO OUR PLANET--
YOURSELF,
SCIENCE
OFFICER,
MEDICAL OFFICER,
COMMUNICATIONS
OFFICER,
AND NAVIGATOR.
ANY MEETINGS
OR DISCUSSIONS
CAN BE HELD ABOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
IF YOU DO NOT
COME WITH ME,
YOUR ENGINES
WILL BE DESTROYED
AND YOU WILL REMAIN
IN ORBIT HERE
FOREVER.
I MUST SAY, THAT'S
A GRACIOUS INVITATION.
THERE IS A WORD.
AMONG US THERE IS NO
CORRESPONDING MEANING,
BUT IT SEEMS
TO MEAN SOMETHING
TO YOU HUMANS.
AND WHAT IS THAT WORD?
PLEASE.
OUR PLANET'S SURFACE
IS WHAT YOU CLASSIFY
AS K-TYPE--
ADAPTABLE FOR HUMANS
BY USE OF PRESSURE DOMES
AND LIFE-SUPPORT
SYSTEMS.
I HAVE BROUGHT THEM.
HE IS WAITING.
IF YOU WILL
FOLLOW US, PLEASE?
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
WELCOME ABOARD, KIRK.
IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME, EH?
HARRY MUDD.
WELL, TO BE ABSOLUTELY
ACCURATE, LADDIE BUCK,
YOU SHOULD REFER TO ME
AS MUDD THE FIRST,
RULER OF THIS ENTIRE
SOVEREIGN PLANET.
RULER?
HARRY, I WANT
CONTROL OF MY SHIP
RETURNED IMMEDIATELY.
WE HAVE NO INTENTION
OF STAYING AS
YOUR GUESTS.
WELL, I'M AFRAID
THERE'S A BIT OF
A PROBLEM THERE.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
ALICE...
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
NOW, NOW, NOW, NOW,
JAMIE BOY,
LET'S HAVE
NO UNAUTHORIZED
COMMUNICATIONS.
YOU KNOW THIS MAN,
CAPTAIN?
OH, DO I KNOW HIM.
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD--
THIEF...
OH, COME NOW.
SWINDLER AND CON MAN...
ENTREPRENEUR.
LIAR AND ROGUE.
DID I LEAVE YOU
WITH THAT IMPRESSION?
HE BELONGS IN JAIL,
WHICH IS WHERE
I THOUGHT
I LEFT YOU, MUDD.
AND THEREBY
HANGS A TALE,
BUT LOOK AROUND YOU, KIRK.
QUITE A PLACE HERE,
ISN'T IT?
I HOPE YOU'RE ALL
GOING TO ENJOY IT.
MUDD, I WANT
THAT TRAINED
MACHINE OF YOURS
NORMAN TO DEACTIVATE
THE TRIGGER
MECHANISM
AND FREE MY SHIP.
I SHALL DO THAT, KIRK,
WHEN I'M READY.
I'M TELLING YOU NOW.
AND I DO THE TELLING
ON THIS PLANET,
KIRK, OLD BOY.
YOU DO THE LISTENING.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL LISTEN.
WHAT ARE YOU
TELLING?
OOH! MERELY THAT YOU
MIGHT AS WELL
START ENJOYING
YOURSELVES.
IT'S REALLY A VERY,
VERY NICE PLACE,
AND YOU'RE ALL
GOING TO BE HERE
QUITE PROBABLY
FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIVES.
HA HA HA HA!
HARRY MUDD,
LIAR AND AN OUTLAW
AND IN DEEP TROUBLE.
I WANT NAVIGATIONAL
CONTROL RESTORED,
MY SHIP RELEASED.
SORRY. THAT WOULD BE
AGAINST THE LAW, MY LAW,
DECREED BY MUDD THE FIRST,
VOTED IN
BY THE RESIDENT POPULATION.
HEH HEH HEH.
LOVELY, AREN'T THEY?
YOU MUST ADMIT, KIRK,
THAT I STILL RETAIN
MY EYE FOR BEAUTY.
I DECREED THAT I SHOULD
ALWAYS BE SURROUNDED BY IT,
AND MY DECREES
ALWAYS COME TO PASS.
I'VE HAD 500 OF THEM MADE UP
TO ATTEND ME...
ALL OF THEM IDENTICAL--
BEAUTIFUL...
COMPLIANT...
OBEDIENT.
OF THE SAME MODEL?
THAT SEEMS
RATHER REDUNDANT.
I HAVE A FONDNESS
FOR THIS PARTICULAR MODEL,
MR. SPOCK,
WHICH YOU, UNFORTUNATELY,
ARE ILL-EQUIPPED
TO APPRECIATE.
UH, TA TA TA TA.
[SNICKERING]
ALL RIGHT, HARRY,
EXPLAIN.
HOW DID YOU
GET HERE?
WE LEFT YOU
IN CUSTODY
AFTER THAT AFFAIR
ON THE RIGEL MINING
PLANET.
YES. WELL,
I ORGANIZED A TECHNICAL
INFORMATION SERVICE--
BRINGING MODERN
INDUSTRIAL TECHNIQUES
TO BACKWARD PLANETS,
MAKING AVAILABLE
CERTAIN VALUABLE PATENTS
TO STRUGGLING
YOUNG CIVILIZATIONS
THROUGHOUT THE GALAXY.
DID YOU PAY ROYALTIES
TO THE OWNERS
OF THOSE PATENTS?
UH...
WELL, ACTUALLY, KIRK,
AS A DEFENDER
OF THE FREE ENTERPRISE SYSTEM,
I FOUND MYSELF
IN A--
IN A RATHER
AMBIGUOUS CONFLICT
AS A MATTER
OF PRINCIPLE.
HE DID NOT
PAY ROYALTIES.
KNOWLEDGE, SIR,
SHOULD BE FREE TO ALL.
WHO CAUGHT YOU?
THAT, SIR, IS
AN OUTRAGEOUS ASSUMPTION.
YES. WHO CAUGHT YOU?
I, UH...I SOLD THE DENEBIANS
ALL THE RIGHTS
TO A VULCAN
FUEL SYNTHESIZER.
AND THE DENEBIANS
CONTACTED THE VULCANS.
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
THAT'S WHAT
I WOULD HAVE DONE.
WELL, IT'S TYPICAL
POLICE MENTALITY.
THEY'VE GOT
NO SENSE OF HUMOR.
THEY ARRESTED ME.
OH, I FIND THAT
SHOCKING.
WORSE THAN THAT.
DO YOU KNOW THE PENALTY
FOR FRAUD IS ON DENEB 5?
THE GUILTY PARTY
HAS HIS CHOICE--
DEATH BY ELECTROCUTION,
DEATH BY GAS,
DEATH BY PHASER,
DEATH BY HANGING--
THE KEY WORD IN YOUR
ENTIRE PERORATION,
MR. SPOCK,
WAS...D-DEATH.
BARBARIANS.
WELL, OF COURSE,
I LEFT.
HE BROKE JAIL.
I BORROWED
TRANSPORTATION.
HE STOLE
A SPACESHIP.
THE PATROL REACTED
IN A HOSTILE MANNER.
THEY FIRED
AT HIM.
THEY'VE GOT NO RESPECT
FOR PRIVATE PROPERTY.
THEY DAMAGED
THE BLOODY SPACESHIP.
WELL, I GOT AWAY,
BUT I COULDN'T NAVIGATE,
SO I WANDERED OUT
THROUGH UNMAPPED SPACE,
AND--AND HERE I FOUND...
MUDD.
YOU WENT TO SUBSTANTIAL
RISK AND EFFORT
TO BRING
A STARSHIP HERE.
LOGICALLY, YOU MUST HAVE
A COMPELLING MOTIVE.
SPOCK, YOU'RE GOING
TO LOVE IT HERE.
THEY ALL TALK
JUST THE WAY YOU DO.
GET ON WITH IT,
HARRY.
YES, WELL,
RIGHT, LADDIE BUCK.
SO HERE I AM
IN A PLANET
WITH OVER 200,000
HARD-WORKING,
HAPPY ANDROIDS,
ALL OF WHOM EXIST MERELY
TO SERVE MY EVERY...
WHIM.
IT'S ABSOLUTE...PARADISE.
THEN I AM UNABLE
TO DISCERN YOUR PROBLEM.
THEY WON'T LET ME GO.
THEY WANT TO STUDY ME.
THEY WANT TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT HUMAN BEINGS.
THEY PICKED
A FINE REPRESENTATIVE.
WATCH YOUR TONGUE, LAD.
YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT MUDD THE FIRST.
WELL, ANYWAY,
I RAN OUT OF IDEAS.
I SIMPLY
RAN OUT OF THINGS
FOR THEM TO DO,
AND THEY INSISTED
THAT I BRING THEM
MORE HUMAN BEINGS.
THEY NEED HUMAN BEINGS
TO SERVE, TO STUDY.
SO I HAD TO PROMISE THEM
A PRIME SAMPLE.
A STARSHIP CAPTAIN--
BRIGHT, LOYAL,
FEARLESS,
AND IMAGINATIVE.
ANY CAPTAIN
WOULD HAVE DONE.
I WAS JUST LUCKY ENOUGH
TO GET YOU.
SO YOU ARE GOING TO
TAKE OVER FOR ME HERE,
AND I GET OFF THIS
ROCK AND BACK TO
CIVILIZATION.
I THINK NOT, HARRY.
YOU MISUNDERSTAND
ME, LAD.
I'M NOT ASKING YOU.
I'M TELLING YOU.
YOU'VE NO CHOICE.
SHOW THEM
TO THEIR QUARTERS.
- YES, MY LORD MUDD.
THIS WAY,
PLEASE.
HARRY, WHAT'S THIS?
AH.
THAT, GENTLEMEN,
IS A SHRINE
TO THE MEMORY
OF MY BELOVED STELLA.
WHO?
STELLA, MY WIFE.
DEAD?
OH, NO, NO, NO.
MERELY DESERTED.
YOU SEE, GENTLEMEN,
BEHIND EVERY GREAT MAN
THERE IS A WOMAN
URGING HIM ON.
AND SO IT WAS
WITH MY STELLA.
SHE URGED ME ON
INTO OUTER SPACE.
NOT THAT SHE MEANT TO,
BUT WITH HER CONTINUAL,
ETERNAL,
CONFOUNDED NAGGING--
WELL, I THINK OF HER
CONSTANTLY,
AND EVERY TIME I DO
I GO FURTHER OUT
INTO SPACE.
THAT'S VERY
INTERESTING.
YOU LEAVE
YOUR WIFE
AND THEN
BRING HER ALONG.
I HAD THE ANDROIDS
CONSTRUCT A PERFECT
REPLICA OF STELLA
SO THAT I COULD
GAZE UPON HER
AND REJOICE
IN HER ABSENCE.
GENTLEMEN, ATTEND.
STELLA, DEAR.
MM, HARCOURT.
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD,
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN UP TO?
NOTHING GOOD,
I'M SURE.
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU,
YOU LAZY,
GOOD-FOR-NOTHING--
SHUT UP.
NOTHING...
THING...THING...
HA HA HA!
MARVELOUS, ISN'T IT?
I FINALLY HAVE
THE LAST WORD WITH HER
AND WITH YOU.
YOU WILL FIND THIS
QUITE COMFORTABLE.
YOUR QUARTERS ARE
DOWN THE HALL.
IF THERE IS
ANYTHING YOU NEED...
YES, MY SHIP.
WE ARE NOT
PROGRAMMED
TO RESPOND
IN THAT AREA.
NORMAN,
WHO CREATED YOU?
THE MAKERS
DESIGNED US.
THEY CAME FROM THE GALAXY
OF ANDROMEDA.
THEN YOUR MAKERS
WEREN'T HUMANOIDS.
THEY WERE, AS YOU SAY,
QUITE HUMANOID,
BUT, UNLIKE
YOUR CIVILIZATION,
ROBOTS WERE COMMON.
WE PERFORMED THE NECESSARY
SERVICE FUNCTIONS
AND FREED OUR MAKERS
TO EVOLVE
A PERFECT SOCIAL ORDER.
WHAT BECAME OF THEM?
OUR HOME PLANET'S SUN
BECAME A NOVA.
ONLY A FEW EXPLORATORY
OUTPOSTS SURVIVED.
THIS UNIT,
MYSELF,
WAS PART OF
ONE SUCH OUTPOST
IN YOUR GALAXY.
THEN SOME OF YOUR MAKERS
SURVIVED.
NO, CAPTAIN.
THEY DIED OVER
THE STRETCH OF TIME.
WHOM DO YOU
SERVE NOW?
- WE SERVE HARRY MUDD.
HE HAS GIVEN US
PURPOSE AGAIN.
IT IS NECESSARY
TO HAVE PURPOSE.
WE LACKED IT
FOR A LONG TIME.
WE HAVE A VERY
EXTENSIVE LIBRARY
SECTION
FOR YOUR AMUSEMENT.
OUR RESEARCH LABORATORIES
AND WORKSHOPS
ARE EXTREMELY
WELL-EQUIPPED.
- YOU ARE FREE TO VISIT THEM.
ALL RIGHT.
WE MIGHT LATER.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WOULD YOU MIND
LEAVING US?
- WHY SHOULD WE LEAVE YOU?
BECAUSE WE DON'T
LIKE YOU.
NOW...
BUP BUP BUP.
WELL, OPINIONS?
I THINK WE'RE
IN A LOT OF TROUBLE.
THAT'S
A GREAT HELP,
MR. CHEKOV.
BONES?
WELL, I THINK
MR. CHEKOV'S RIGHT.
WE ARE IN A LOT
OF TROUBLE.
SPOCK--AND IF YOU SAY
WE'RE IN A LOT
OF TROUBLE--
WE ARE.
AND WE MUST
DIRECT OUR ATTACK
TO THE HEART
OF THE MATTER.
OBVIOUSLY,
THIS MANY ANDROIDS
CANNOT OPERATE
INDEPENDENTLY.
THERE MUST BE A CENTRAL
CONTROL SYSTEM
WHICH GUIDES THE ENTIRE
ANDROID POPULATION.
TRY AND FIND IT.
THE REST OF YOU,
LOOK AROUND. LEARN
EVERYTHING YOU CAN.
I'LL SEE WHAT ELSE
I CAN FIND OUT FROM
MR. MUDD. LET'S GO.
I TRUST YOU ARE
ENJOYING YOURSELF,
MR. SPOCK.
VERY INTERESTING.
THIS IS A MOST
UNUSUAL DEVICE.
IT IS OUR CENTRAL
CONTROL COMPLEX.
OH?
DID I UNDERSTAND
THERE ARE MORE THAN
200,000 OF YOU?
207,809.
THIS WOULD SEEM TO BE
A SIMPLE RELAY CENTER.
ARE ALL OF YOU CONTROLLED
THROUGH THIS DEVICE?
[BEEPING]
I AM NOT PROGRAMMED
TO RESPOND IN THIS AREA.
OH, THAT'S...
QUITE UNDERSTANDABLE.
THESE ARE
OUR BARBARA SERIES.
THE BODY IS COVERED
WITH A SELF-RENEWING
PLASTIC
OVER A SKELETON
OF BERYLLIUM-TITANIUM ALLOY.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
I SHOULD SAY SO.
WELL, I MUST SAY
I LIKE THE STYLING.
THEY WERE, OF COURSE,
MADE TO MY PERSONAL
SPECIFICATIONS,
AS INDEED WERE
THE MAIZIE SERIES,
THE TRUDY SERIES,
AND PARTICULARLY
THE ANNABELLE SERIES.
DON'T YOU BELIEVE
IN MALE ANDROIDS, HARRY?
MALE?
WELL, I SUPPOSE
THEY HAVE THEIR USES.
HOW LONG DOES A BODY
LIKE THAT LAST?
NONE OF OUR ANDROID BODIES
HAS EVER WORN OUT.
HOWEVER, THE ESTIMATED
DURATION OF THIS MODEL
IS 500,000 YEARS.
500,000...YEARS?
OUR MEDI-ROBOTS ARE ABLE
TO PLACE A HUMAN BRAIN
WITHIN A STRUCTURALLY
COMPATIBLE ANDROID BODY.
IMMORTALITY...
AND ETERNAL BEAUTY.
HMM?
CAPTAIN, I'VE JUST HAD
A MOST FASCINATING
MEETING WITH NORMAN,
AND I'M CONVINCED
THAT I'VE DISCOVERED
A VERY IMPORTANT
INCONSISTENCY.
WELL, I'M SO GLAD
YOU ENJOYED IT, DOCTOR.
JIM, YOU SHOULD SEE
THE RESEARCH FACILITIES.
THEY'VE GOT A LAB
DOWN THERE THAT...
WELL, I COULD SPEND THE REST
OF MY LIFE STUDYING IT.
I DO SO ADMIRE A MAN
WHO DEVOTES HIMSELF
TO KNOWLEDGE.
DON'T LOSE
YOUR HEAD, BONES.
NOBODY'S
STAYING ANYWHERE.
STUBBORN, KIRK.
STUBBORN.
I WOULDN'T BE BORED,
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
LET GO OF ME!
NOW WHAT ARE YOU DOING...
THE LAST ONE, LORD.
SPLENDID. SPLENDID.
WELCOME TO MUDD,
MR. SCOTT.
HARRY MUDD!
OH, YOU BOGUS
FRAT, YOU.
YOU'RE THE CAUSE
OF ALL THIS, ARE YOU?
SCOTTY, YOU
WERE ORDERED
TO STAY ABOARD.
AYE, SIR, AND I STAYED UNTIL
THAT FEMALE GARGANTUA
THREW ME INTO
THE TRANSPORTER BEAMS.
WHAT DOES SHE MEAN,
THE LAST ONE?
OH, DIDN'T I TELL YOU, KIRK?
I BEAMED A FEW DOZEN
ANDROIDS UP TO YOUR SHIP.
THEY'VE BEEN SENDING
YOUR CREW TO THE SURFACE
FOR THE PAST COUPLE OF HOURS.
THEY'RE ALL DOWN NOW.
ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
YOU CAN'T BEAM DOWN
AN ENTIRE CREW OF A
SPACESHIP.
SOMEBODY
HAS TO BE ON BOARD.
WELL, THERE IS
AN ENTIRE CREW ABOARD--
AN ENTIRE CREW
OF ANDROIDS.
THEY LEARN
VERY QUICKLY, CAPTAIN.
THE FACT IS...
I'VE TAKEN OVER
YOUR WHOLE SHIP.
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO ABOUT IT.
HARRY...
HARRY, YOU'LL NEVER
GET AWAY WITH IT.
[GASPING]
WELL, WHO'S
TO STOP ME?
STARFLEET.
BUT NOW, CAPTAIN, NOW
I HAVE A SHIP OF MY OWN,
AND IT'S AS FAST AS ANY
IN THE FLEET.
SO HOW WILL THEY
CATCH ME, EH?
JUST THINK OF IT,
LADDIE BUCK.
HARRY MUDD WITH HIS
OWN CREW OF LOVELIES
ABOARD YOUR VESSEL.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
I'M TRYING NOT TO.
ALICE.
HE COULD SUCCESSFULLY
ACCOMPLISH IT, CAPTAIN.
I'VE QUESTIONED A NUMBER
OF THE ANDROIDS,
AND THEY ARE TOTALLY
LOYAL TO MUDD.
PERHAPS OF MORE CONCERN
IS THE FACT THAT
THIS ANDROID POPULATION
CAN LITERALLY PROVIDE
ANYTHING A HUMAN BEING
COULD ASK FOR
IN UNLIMITED QUANTITY.
YES, I KNOW. THAT'S
WHAT WORRIES ME.
HOW WILL MY CREW
REACT IN A WORLD
WHERE THEY CAN HAVE
ABSOLUTELY EVERYTHING
THEY WANT
SIMPLY BY ASKING FOR IT?
- YOU DESIRE SOMETHING, LORD?
OH, YES, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE ALICE, UH...
- 118.
- 118...
AND YOU'RE
ALICE, UH...
- 322.
OH, WELL, IT DOESN'T
MAKE MUCH DIFFERENCE.
YOU'RE BOTH LOVELY.
- THANK YOU, MY LORD.
YOU DESIRE
SOMETHING ELSE, LORD?
WHAT A SHAME
YOU'RE NOT REAL.
WE ARE REAL, MY LORD.
OH, I MEAN REAL GIRLS.
WE ARE PROGRAMMED
TO FUNCTION
AS HUMAN FEMALES,
LORD.
YOU ARE?
- YES, MY LORD.
HARRY MUDD
PROGRAMMED YOU?
- YES, MY LORD.
THAT UNPRINCIPLED,
EVIL-MINDED,
LECHEROUS KULAK
HARRY MUDD PROGRAMMED YOU?
- YES, MY LORD.
THIS PLACE IS EVEN BETTER
THAN LENINGRAD.
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
HAND-WORKED TO
THE FINEST TOLERANCES,
MICROVISION,
AND A NANOPULSE LASER.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
HER LIKE BEFORE.
YOU MAY COMMAND US
TO MAKE ANYTHING
FOR YOU
OR DO THE WORK
YOURSELF
FOR PLEASURE.
YOU MAY HAVE
THE SERVICES
OF ANY NUMBER
OF CRAFTSMEN,
EXCLUSIVE USE
OF THE COMPUTER FACILITIES,
ANYTHING.
CAPTAIN, YOU SHOULD
SEE THIS SHOP.
WHY, THEY HAVE FACILITIES
WE'VE NEVER EVEN THOUGHT OF.
IS THAT THE WAY
YOU'RE GONNA
DO IT, MUDD?
HIT MY PEOPLE
AT THEIR
WEAKEST POINT?
WE ONLY WISH
TO MAKE YOU HAPPY
AND COMFORTABLE, CAPTAIN.
IF WE ARE TO SERVE
YOUR KIND,
WE MUST
UNDERSTAND YOU.
OUR LORD HARRY MUDD
WAS ONLY ONE EXAMPLE
FOR US.
NOW WE ARE LEARNING
A GREAT DEAL
FROM ALL OF YOU.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE ARE,
BIRDS IN A GILDED CAGE.
QUESTION IS, HOW DO
WE GET OUT OF HERE?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
BUT IT'S A VERY NICE
GILDED CAGE.
Uhura: AND IT IS
A VERY PLEASANT
PLACE, CAPTAIN.
Scotty: WHAT DID THEY
OFFER YOU, UHURA?
OH, NOTHING
REALLY IMPORTANT,
JUST IMMORTALITY.
ALL RIGHT. WE'RE GETTING
BACK TO THE SHIP,
AND DON'T YOU FORGET IT.
STRAIGHTEN UP!
THIS MAY BE
A GILDED CAGE
FILLED WITH EVERYTHING
YOU ALWAYS WANTED,
BUT IT'S STILL A CAGE.
WE DON'T BELONG HERE.
WE BELONG ON THAT SHIP
UP THERE.
DO YOU REQUIRE
SOMETHING, LORD?
NO. YES!
MY SHIP.
I AM NOT PROGRAMMED...
"TO RESPOND
IN THAT AREA."
YES, I KNOW.
IS THERE ANYTHING
ANY OF YOU REQUIRE
TO PLEASE YOU?
ALICE...
GIVE US
BACK OUR SHIP
TO PLEASE US.
RETURN US
TO OUR SHIP
BECAUSE WE
DESIRE IT.
WE ARE PROGRAMMED
TO SERVE.
WE SHALL SERVE YOU
TO YOUR BEST INTERESTS
TO MAKE YOU HAPPY.
BUT WE'RE
UNHAPPY HERE.
PLEASE EXPLAIN UNHAPPY.
UNHAPPINESS IS THE STATE
WHICH OCCURS IN THE HUMAN
WHEN WANTS AND DESIRES
ARE NOT FULFILLED.
WHICH WANTS AND DESIRES
OF YOURS ARE NOT FULFILLED?
WE WANT THE
"ENTERPRISE."
[BEEPING]
THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS NOT A WANT OR A DESIRE.
IT IS A MECHANICAL DEVICE.
NO. IT'S
A BEAUTIFUL LADY,
AND WE LOVE HER.
[BEEPING]
ILLOGICAL. ILLOGICAL.
ALL UNITS RELATE.
ALL UNITS.
NORMAN, COORDINATE.
[STEADY BEEP]
UNHAPPINESS
DOES NOT RELATE.
WE MUST STUDY THIS.
INTERESTING.
FASCINATING.
BONES, HAVE YOU HAD
TIME TO TAKE
ANY PSYCHOLOGICAL
READINGS
OF THE ANDROIDS?
I DID, AND YOU CAN
FORGET IT.
THEY'RE PERFECT,
FLAWLESS,
MENTALLY AND PHYSICALLY.
NO WEAKNESSES,
PERFECTLY DISCIPLINED,
NO VICES, NO FEARS,
NO FAULTS,
JUST A SENSE OF PURPOSE.
BELIEVE ME.
THERE'S NOTHING
TOUGHER TO OVERCOME,
EVEN AMONG HUMANS.
YES. THAT'S WHAT
THIS CREW NEEDS,
A LITTLE SENSE
OF PURPOSE.
MUDD, A FEW QUESTIONS
I WANT TO ASK YOU.
OOH! AFRAID
I WON'T HAVE TIME
TO ANSWER THEM.
MY BAGS ARE ALL PACKED.
THE ANDROIDS WILL
TAKE THE "ENTERPRISE"
OUT OF ORBIT IN
LESS THAN 24 HOURS,
BUT IT'S BEEN A REAL PLEASURE
HAVING YOU HERE, KIRK.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN GET FOR YOU?
YES. MY SHIP.
OH, YOU'RE A STUBBORN
FELLOW, AREN'T YOU?
BUT I DON'T MIND.
I DON'T MIND
THAT AT ALL
BECAUSE I'LL
BE LEAVING HERE
QUICKLY ENOUGH,
AND THEN YOU
CAN BE STUBBORN
AT YOUR OWN LEISURE.
ONE LAST TIME.
STELLA...
DEAR...
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD,
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHAT HAVE YOU
BEEN UP TO?
HAVE YOU BEEN
DRINKING AGAIN?
YOU MISERABLE SOT!
YOU GOOD-FOR-NOTHING--
SHUT UP!
THING...THING...
THING...
ALICE NUMBER 2,
MY LITTLE LOVE.
WILL YOU HAVE MY BAGS
TRANSPORTED UP TO THE SHIP?
All: NO, MY LORD MUDD.
WHAT?
WE CAN NO LONGER
TAKE YOUR ORDERS,
HARRY MUDD.
WHY NOT?
OUR MAKERS
WERE WISE.
THEY PROGRAMMED US
TO SERVE.
YES, BUT THAT'S
WHAT I'M SAYING.
PUT MY BAGS
ON THE SHIP.
HARRY, I THINK THEY HAVE
SOMETHING ELSE IN MIND.
YOU ARE CORRECT,
CAPTAIN.
HARRY MUDD IS FLAWED,
EVEN FOR A HUMAN BEING.
WE RECOGNIZED THIS
FROM THE BEGINNING
BUT USED HIS KNOWLEDGE
TO OBTAIN MORE SPECIMENS.
YOUR SPECIES
IS SELF-DESTRUCTIVE.
YOU NEED OUR HELP.
WE PREFER
TO HELP OURSELVES.
WE MAKE MISTAKES,
BUT WE'RE HUMAN.
AND MAYBE
THAT'S THE WORD
THAT BEST
EXPLAINS US.
WE WILL NOT HARM YOU,
BUT WE WILL
TAKE THE STARSHIP,
AND YOU WILL REMAIN
ON THIS PLANET.
NOW, LOOK HERE.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT!
NOW, LISTEN.
TO SERVE US,
YOU MUST OBEY US.
All: NO, MY LORD MUDD.
ALICE NUMBER 1,
OBEY ME.
PUT MY BAGS
ON THAT SHIP!
WE CANNOT
ALLOW ANY RACE
AS GREEDY
AND CORRUPTIBLE
AS YOURS
TO HAVE FREE RUN
OF THE GALAXY.
I'M CURIOUS, NORMAN,
JUST HOW DO YOU INTEND
TO STOP THEM?
WE SHALL SERVE THEM.
THEIR KIND WILL BE EAGER
TO ACCEPT OUR SERVICE.
SOON THEY WILL BECOME
COMPLETELY DEPENDENT
UPON US.
THEIR AGGRESSIVE
AND ACQUISITIVE
INSTINCTS
WILL BE UNDER
OUR CONTROL.
WE SHALL...
TAKE CARE OF THEM.
EMINENTLY PRACTICAL.
THE WHOLE GALAXY
CONTROLLED BY...
YOUR KIND?
YES, CAPTAIN.
AND WE SHALL
SERVE THEM,
AND YOU WILL BE HAPPY...
AND CONTROLLED.
SO FAR,
THIS THING HAS HAD
ITS AMUSING ASPECTS,
BUT THAT THREAT
THE ANDROIDS MADE
ABOUT TAKING OVER
ALL THE HUMANS
IN THE GALAXY
IS NOT VERY FUNNY.
INDEED, IT IS NOT.
THEY MAY QUITE POSSIBLY
BE ABLE TO ACCOMPLISH IT.
TAKE MY WORD FOR IT.
THEY CAN.
WHATEVER METHOD WE USE TO STOP
THEM, WE MUST MAKE HASTE.
THEY HAVE ONLY TO INSTALL
SOME CYBERNETIC DEVICES
ABOARD THE "ENTERPRISE,"
AND THEY'LL BE ABLE
TO LEAVE ORBIT.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
SO MUCH?
I ASKED THEM.
OH.
WHY SHOULDN'T THEY
ANSWER OUR QUESTIONS?
THEY DON'T THINK WE CAN
DO ANYTHING TO STOP THEM.
YOU'RE SO SMART, KIRK,
YOU AND THIS
POINTY-EARED
THINKING MACHINE
OF YOURS.
WELL, YOU'D BETTER
DO SOMETHING
BECAUSE I'M AS ANXIOUS
TO GET OFF THIS
RUDDY ROCK AS YOU ARE.
I SEEM TO REMEMBER
THAT YOU WANTED
TO LEAVE US
ON THIS RUDDY ROCK
AND LEAVE
BY YOURSELF.
UH...
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT
TO WORK WITH?
WELL, CAPTAIN,
ANDROIDS AND ROBOTS,
WELL, THEY'RE JUST NOT
CAPABLE OF INDEPENDENT,
CREATIVE THOUGHT.
YET THE DEVICE
THAT NORMAN CLAIMS
TO BE THEIR
CENTRAL CONTROL
IS TOTALLY INADEQUATE
TO THE TASK OF DIRECTING
MORE THAN 200,000
OF THEM.
I AGREE.
WHAT IN YOUR OPINION
DOES DIRECT THEM?
THERE ARE A LARGE NUMBER
OF ALICES AND TRUDYS,
MAIZIES, ANNABELLES,
AND ACCORDING
TO MY RESEARCH,
A HERMAN SERIES,
AN OSCAR SERIES,
A WHOLE PLETHORA
OF SERIES, IN FACT,
BUT ONLY ONE NORMAN.
HMM.
NORMAN.
WHEN I TOLD
ONE OF THE ALICES
THAT THE "ENTERPRISE"
WAS A LOVELY LADY
AND WE LOVED HER,
SHE SAID, "NORMAN,
COORDINATE."
WHY NORMAN?
UNLESS...
TO FUNCTION
AS THEY DO,
EACH ANDROID MIND
MUST BE ONE COMPONENT
OF A MASS BRAIN
LINKED THROUGH
A CENTRAL LOCUS...
NAMED NORMAN.
FORMING ONE GIGANTIC,
HIGHLY INTELLIGENT MIND.
AND THE GLOWING
BADGES...
THEY INDICATE
THE MIND IN OPERATION.
THAT WOULD SEEM LOGICAL.
YES, LOGICAL.
THAT'S WHAT IT IS,
AND THAT IN TURN
GIVES US A WEAPON THAT
WE CAN USE AGAINST THEM.
WE MUST USE
WILD, INSANE,
IRRATIONAL ILLOGIC
AIMED RIGHT AT NORMAN!
CAPTAIN,
YOU SING AND DANCE
AS WELL AS ANYONE
I'VE EVER SEEN,
BUT WHAT THE DEVIL
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT WOULD SEEM TO BE
A SOUND AND, PERHAPS,
OUR ONLY OPPORTUNITY.
OPPORTUNITY?
NOW, LISTEN, SPOCK,
YOU MAY BE
A WONDERFUL
SCIENCE OFFICER,
BUT, BELIEVE ME,
YOU COULDN'T SELL
FAKE PATENTS
TO YOUR MOTHER.
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY I SHOULD CARE
TO INDUCE MY MOTHER
TO PURCHASE
FALSIFIED PATENTS.
FORGET IT.
LET'S GET TO THE POINT.
HARRY, YOU SAID YOU
WANTED TO HELP. DO YOU?
CAPTAIN, THE KIND
OF A WHOLESOME,
ANTISEPTIC GALAXY
THAT THESE ANDROIDS
WOULD RUN
WOULD BE PURGATORY
FOR A MAN LIKE ME.
THAT'S FINE, HARRY.
THE ANDROIDS WILL
BE EXPECTING US
TO MAKE A BREAK
FOR IT,
AND THAT'S WHERE
YOU COME IN.
WHAT CAN I DO?
NOTHING, HARRY.
JUST...
GO TO SLEEP.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
OH, NOW--NOW--
WAIT A MINUTE,
GENTLEMEN.
NO, WHAT I--I--I--AAH--
HAD IN MIND WAS
ACTUALLY MORE IN THE LINE
OF A FEW WORDS
OF SAGE COUNSEL,
AS IT WERE, ADVICE...
OOH! HARRY, I DO
BELIEVE YOU'RE
PUTTING ON WEIGHT.
[CHIME]
YES?
WE HAVE
A MEDICAL PROBLEM.
YOUR EX-LORD
HARRY MUDD.
HE IS HUMAN.
YOU WILL HAVE TO
CARE FOR HIM.
WE ARE CARING
FOR HIM,
BUT OUR DOCTOR
NEEDS HIS MEDICAL
EQUIPMENT
ABOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
THE STARSHIP IS
FORBIDDEN TO HUMANS.
YOU'RE PROGRAMMED
TO SERVE.
IF WE'RE NOT
ALLOWED ACCESS
TO OUR
MEDICAL EQUIPMENT,
HARRY MUDD WILL DIE,
HE WILL CEASE
TO FUNCTION.
YOU WILL HAVE
FAILED TO SERVE.
[BEEPING]
I AM DIRECTED TO
OBSERVE THE SITUATION.
HE IS
MALFUNCTIONING?
HE IS DYING.
IF YOU TAKE HIM
TO YOUR SICK BAY,
WILL HE BE REPAIRED?
OH, YES.
NO. THEY'RE LYING.
IT'S A TRICK.
DR. McCOY
INJECTED SOMETHING
INTO HARRY MUDD
TO MAKE HIM
LOOK SICK.
IT'S A TRICK
TO GET BACK ON BOARD
AND SABOTAGE THE SHIP.
YOUR REQUEST
IS REFUSED.
UHURA, WHY DID YOU
TELL HER?
BECAUSE I WANT
AN ANDROID BODY.
I WANT IMMORTALITY.
I'LL LIVE FOREVER,
CAPTAIN.
I'LL BE YOUNG
AND BEAUTIFUL.
YOU HAVE BEEN
OF ASSISTANCE.
WE SHALL FULFILL
OUR OBLIGATION.
THANK YOU.
THE PROGRAMMING FOR
YOUR BODY WILL BE
COMPLETED
BEFORE WE LEAVE.
UHURA...
BEAUTIFUL!
I HALF BELIEVED IT
MYSELF.
WELL, THE ANDROIDS
WERE EXPECTING
AN ATTEMPT,
AND NOW WE'VE
MADE IT.
WHAT'S NEXT,
CAPTAIN?
NEXT, WE TAKE
THE ALICES
ON A TRIP
THROUGH WONDERLAND.
[BELL CHIMES]
- DO YOU REQUIRE SOMETHING?
YES.
YOUR ATTENTION.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
THEY'RE CELEBRATING.
WHAT ARE THEY
CELEBRATING?
THEIR CAPTIVITY.
YOU ENJOY THE MUSIC?
MUSIC?
[BEEPING]
THANK YOU,
GENTLEMEN.
LOVELY LADY.
YOU DANCE DIVINELY.
THANK YOU,
KIND SIR.
WHY DOES SHE
STRIKE HIM?
SHE LIKES HIM.
MR. CHEKOV...
THE FLOOR IS NO PLACE
FOR AN OFFICER.
ATTENTION!
NOW STAND
ABSOLUTELY STILL.
YES, CAPTAIN.
HEY!
HEY! HEY!
THAT'S MUCH BETTER,
MR. CHEKOV.
IT...IS ILLOGICAL.
YOUR STATEMENT
IS ILLOGICAL.
HEY! HEY! HEY!
HEY!
HEY! HEY!
HEY! HEY! HEY!
HOW DOES
IT LOOK?
COMPLETELY
INNER DIRECTED,
OBLIVIOUS
TO EVERYTHING.
GOOD. I WONDER
HOW SPOCK'S DOING.
OF COURSE.
YOUR COMPUTATIONS
WOULD INEVITABLY LEAD
TO A TOTAL DESCRIPTION
OF THE PARABOLIC
INTERSECTION
OF DIMENSION
WITH DIMENSION.
MR. SPOCK, YOU HAVE
A REMARKABLY LOGICAL
AND ANALYTICAL MIND.
THANK YOU.
IS THERE SOME
SIGNIFICANCE
TO THIS ACTION?
I LOVE YOU.
HOWEVER, I HATE YOU.
BUT...I'M IDENTICAL
IN EVERY WAY WITH ALICE 27.
YES, OF COURSE.
THAT IS EXACTLY
WHY I HATE YOU,
BECAUSE YOU
ARE IDENTICAL.
[BEEPING]
[STEADY BEEP]
FASCINATING.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S WORKED
SO FAR,
BUT WE'RE
NOT OUT YET.
WELL?
SUCCESS, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE BEEN PRUNING
THE LEAVES
AND BRANCHES
OF THE TREE.
NOW IT IS TIME TO
GET TO WORK
ON THE ROOT.
IF NORMAN IS
THE CONTROL CENTER,
HE SHOULD BE IN A BIND
BY WHAT WE'VE DONE.
IF WE CAN OVERLOAD HIM
FURTHER,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO IMMOBILIZE ALL OF THEM.
DOES EVERYBODY REMEMBER
WHAT TO DO?
AYE, SIR.
AFFIRMATIVE.
ACKNOWLEDGED?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I WANT YOU
TO SURRENDER.
THAT IS ILLOGICAL.
WE CAN MOVE
MORE QUICKLY THAN YOU.
WE ARE INVULNERABLE
TO ATTACK.
WE ARE MUCH STRONGER.
NO, WE ARE
STRONGER,
AND I'LL PROVE IT
TO YOU.
CAN YOU HARM A MAN
THAT YOU'RE PROGRAMMED
TO SERVE?
NO.
BUT YOU
ALREADY HAVE,
NORMAN, LADDIE.
HUMAN BEINGS
DO NOT SURVIVE
ON BREAD ALONE,
YOU POOR,
SOULLESS CREATURE,
BUT ON
THE NOURISHMENTS
OF LIBERTY,
FOR WHAT INDEED
IS A MAN
WITHOUT FREEDOM?
NAUGHT
BUT A MECHANISM
TRAPPED IN
THE COGWHEELS
OF ETERNITY.
YOU OFFER US
ONLY WELL-BEING.
FOOD AND DRINK
AND HAPPINESS
MEAN NOTHING TO US.
WE MUST BE
ABOUT OUR JOB.
SUFFERING,
IN TORMENT AND PAIN,
LABORING
WITHOUT END.
DYING AND CRYING
AND LAMENTING
OVER OUR BURDENS.
- ONLY THIS WAY CAN WE BE HAPPY.
[BEEPING]
THAT IS...
CONTRADICTORY.
IT IS NOT LOGICAL.
MR. SPOCK...
EXPLAIN.
WHY NOT?
LOGIC IS A LITTLE
TWEETING BIRD
CHIRPING
IN A MEADOW.
LOGIC IS A WREATH
OF PRETTY FLOWERS
WHICH SMELL BAD.
ARE YOU SURE YOUR CIRCUITS
ARE REGISTERING CORRECTLY?
YOUR EARS ARE GREEN.
[WAILING]
I CANNOT GO ON!
I'M TIRED OF HAPPINESS.
I'M TIRED
OF COMFORT AND PLEASURE.
I'M READY!
KILL ME! KILL ME!
[ALL IMITATING
PHASER SHOTS]
GOOD-BYE,
CRUEL UNIVERSE.
HE'S DEAD.
YOU...
CANNOT HAVE
KILLED HIM.
YOU HAVE
NO WEAPONS.
SCOTTY.
SCOTTY'S DEAD.
HE HAD TOO MUCH
HAPPINESS,
BUT NOW HE'S HAPPIER
HE'S DEAD,
AND WE'LL MISS HIM.
LET US HEAR IT
FOR OUR POOR, DEAD FRIEND.
[LAUGHING]
WHAT IS A MAN
BUT THAT LOFTY SPIRIT,
THAT SENSE OF...
ENTERPRISE,
THAT DEVOTION TO SOMETHING
THAT CANNOT BE SENSED,
CANNOT BE REALIZED
BUT ONLY DREAMED!
THE HIGHEST REALITY.
BRILLIANT!
BRAVO, BRAVO,
CAPTAIN!
HOW DID YOU LIKE IT?
THAT IS IRRATIONAL,
ILLOGICAL.
DREAMS ARE NOT REAL.
OUR LOGIC
IS TO BE ILLOGICAL.
THAT IS OUR ADVANTAGE.
MR. SPOCK, IT IS TIME.
THE EXPLOSIVE.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
EXPLOSIVE!
DON'T PANIC. WOMEN
AND CHILDREN FIRST.
MR. SPOCK...
ISN'T THAT TOO MUCH
FOR OUR PURPOSES?
I BELIEVE THAT IS
THE CORRECT AMOUNT,
CAPTAIN.
MR. MUDD,
ARE YOU READY?
AYE, AYE!
BE CAREFUL.
I WOULD NOT WANT YOU
TO DROP IT.
[IMITATING ENGINE
WINDING UP]
PLEASE.
CAUTION.
WATCH IT!
DETONATOR.
FUSE.
PRIMER.
MASHIE.
THERE IS
NO EXPLOSIVE.
NO? OBSERVE.
- FORE!
- OH!
- AH!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
BUT THERE WAS...
NO EXPLOSION.
I LIED.
- WHAT?
- HE LIED.
EVERYTHING
HARRY TELLS YOU
IS A LIE.
REMEMBER THAT.
EVERYTHING HARRY
TELLS YOU IS A LIE.
NOW LISTEN TO THIS
CAREFULLY, NORMAN.
I AM LYING.
YOU SAY
YOU ARE LYING,
BUT IF EVERYTHING
YOU SAY IS A LIE,
THEN YOU ARE
TELLING THE TRUTH, BUT...
YOU CANNOT
TELL THE TRUTH
BECAUSE EVERYTHING
YOU SAY IS A LIE,
BUT YOU LIE--
YOU TELL THE TRUTH--
BUT YOU CANNOT,
FOR YOU LIE--
ILLOGICAL!
PLEASE EXPLAIN.
YOU ARE HUMANS.
ONLY HUMANS CAN EXPLAIN
THEIR BEHAVIOR.
PLEASE EXPLAIN.
I AM NOT PROGRAMMED
TO RESPOND IN THAT AREA.
I BELIEVE THEY ARE
ALL IMMOBILIZED,
CAPTAIN.
- GOOD.
- KIRK, OLD MAN...
I'M BEGINNING TO
DEVELOP CONSIDERABLE
RESPECT FOR YOU.
- WHY, THANK YOU.
- WOULD YOU CONSIDER...
ENTERING A PARTNERSHIP
ARRANGEMENT WITH ME?
I'VE GOT SOME IDEAS.
A PARTNERSHIP
ARRANGEMENT?
- YOU AND ME?
- YES.
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
ELSE IN MIND.
LET'S GO.
WELL, YOU MUST BE VERY
UNHAPPY, MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS
A HUMAN EMOTION,
DOCTOR,
WITH WHICH
I'M TOTALLY
UNFAMILIAR.
HOW COULD
I BE UNHAPPY?
WELL, WE FOUND
A WHOLE WORLD OF MINDS
THAT WORK
JUST LIKE YOURS--
LOGICAL, UNEMOTIONAL,
COMPLETELY PRAGMATIC--
AND WE POOR,
IRRATIONAL HUMANS
WHIPPED THEM
IN A FAIR FIGHT.
NOW YOU'LL FIND YOURSELF
BACK AMONG US
ILLOGICAL HUMANS AGAIN.
WHICH I FIND EMINENTLY
SATISFACTORY, DOCTOR,
FOR NOWHERE AM I SO
DESPERATELY NEEDED
AS AMONG A SHIPLOAD
OF ILLOGICAL HUMANS.
TOUCHE, BONES.
Harry: I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF ANYTHING SO REVOLTING.
WE'LL SOON GET
TO THE BOTTOM THI--
KIRK! NOW, WHAT'S
ALL THIS I HEAR
ABOUT MY HAVING
TO STAY HERE?
YES, MUDD.
YOU'VE BEEN PAROLED
TO THE ANDROID POPULATION
OF THIS PLANET.
THE ANDROIDS
HAVE BEEN REPROGRAMMED.
THEIR ORIGINAL PURPOSE
WAS TO ADAPT THIS PLANET
FOR PRODUCTIVE USE.
THEY'LL BEGIN
THAT WORK AGAIN.
BUT WHAT DO I DO?
KIRK, I'M NO SCIENTIST.
NO, YOU'RE
AN IRRITANT.
YOU'LL STAY HERE
AND PROVIDE
A FIRST-CLASS
EXAMPLE
TO THE ANDROIDS
OF A HUMAN FAILURE.
THEY'LL LEARN
BY CLOSE OBSERVATION
HOW TO AVOID
ONES LIKE YOU
IN THE FUTURE.
HOW LONG?
AS LONG AS YOU CONTINUE
TO BE AN IRRITANT,
HARRY.
IT'S UP TO YOU.
WELL...
I SUPPOSE...
THAT TAKING EVERYTHING
INTO, UH, CONSIDERATION,
AS IT WERE,
AND NOTING ALL THE DIFFERENT
POSSIBILITIES,
I COULD MANAGE.
AND AS DETENTION
SENTENCES GO...
THIS ONE ISN'T, UH...
TOO...
UNCOMFORTABLE,
AND I'M BACK
IN THE GALAXY AGAIN!
YES, YOU ARE,
OH, BUT THERE'S
ONE MORE THING,
HARRY.
WE'VE PROGRAMMED
A SPECIAL ANDROID
ATTENDANT
TO TAKE CARE
OF YOUR EVERY NEED.
SHE'LL HELP YOU
FIND AN INCENTIVE
TO WORK
WITH THE ANDROIDS
AND NOT
EXPLOIT THEM.
I CALL THAT
UNEXPECTEDLY CIVIL
OF YOU, CAPTAIN.
YES.
Stella: HARCOURT!
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD,
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN UP TO?
HAVE YOU BEEN
DRINKING AGAIN?
- YOU ANSWER ME!
- STELLA, SHUT UP!
- YOU MISERABLE,
CONNIVING TOAD!
- I ORDER YOU...
- SHUT UP, STELLA!
- GOING OUT ALL NIGHT,
GIVING ME
SUCH SILLY STORIES.
Second Stella: HARCOURT!
OHH!
HARCOURT FENTON MUDD,
YOU'VE BEEN OVEREATING AGAIN
AND DRINKING.
KIRK, YOU CAN'T
DO THIS TO ME.
YOU NEED CONSTANT
SUPERVISION.
IT'S INHUMAN.
I'VE GOT MY WORK
CUT OUT FOR ME.
HARCOURT!
[STELLAS SPEAKING AT ONCE]
NO.
NUMBER 500?
NO, NO, NO.
WHAT HAVE YOU
BEEN UP TO?
[ALL SPEAKING AT ONCE]
KIRK, YOU CAN'T
DO THIS TO ME.
IT'S INHUMAN!
[NAGGING CONTINUES]
GOOD-BYE, HARRY.
HAVE FUN.
[NAGGING CONTINUES]