WE HAVE REACHED
PROJECTED POINT THREE,
CAPTAIN.
ADJUST TO NEW COURSE
201, MARK 15.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
JIM.
HOW IS SHE, DOC?
NO CHANGE.
SMALL THANKS
TO THE STAR FLEET.
NOW, REALLY,
COMMISSIONER,
YOU CAN'T BLAME
THE STAR FLEET.
I SHOULD'VE RECEIVED
THE PROPER INOCULATIONS
AHEAD OF TIME.
SECURO'S DISEASE
IS EXTREMELY RARE.
THE CHANCES OF
ANYONE CONTRACTING IT
ARE LITERALLY
BILLIONS TO ONE.
I WAS SENT TO
EPSILON CANARUS 3
TO PREVENT A WAR, DOCTOR.
THANKS TO THE INEFFICIENCY
OF THE MEDICAL BRANCH
OF THE STAR FLEET,
I'VE BEEN FORCED TO LEAVE
BEFORE MY JOB WAS DONE.
COMMISSIONER, I CAN
ASSURE YOU THAT ONCE WE
REACH THE ENTERPRISE,
WITH ITS
MEDICAL FACILITIES,
WE'LL HAVE YOU BACK
TO YOUR JOB IN TIME FOR
YOU TO PREVENT THAT WAR.
HOW SOON WILL WE
RENDEZVOUS
WITH YOUR SHIP OF
YOURS, CAPTAIN?
IN EXACTLY
4 HOURS, 21 MINUTES,
COMMISSIONER.
CAPTAIN.
YEAH.
WILL YOU CHECK
YOUR AUTOMATIC
SCANNER, PLEASE?
THAT'S ODD. I'VE
NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THAT BEFORE.
NOR HAVE I.
HEADING DIRECTLY TOWARD US
AT WARP SPEED.
STAYING
RIGHT WITH US.
SENSOR READINGS,
MR. SPOCK.
VAGUELY LIKE A CLOUD
OF IONIZED HYDROGEN,
BUT WITH STRONG ERRATIC
ELECTRICAL IMPULSES.
WE'VE GOT IT.
HELM DOES NOT ANSWER,
CAPTAIN.
NEITHER DO THE PODS.
COMMUNICATIONS ARE DEAD.
BUILDING OVERLOAD.
CUT ALL POWER RELAYS.
CUT, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I DEMAND TO KNOW.
YOU ALREADY KNOW
AS MUCH AS WE DO,
MISS HEDFORD.
WHATEVER
THAT THING IS
OUTSIDE,
HE YANKED US
OFF COURSE FROM
THE ENTERPRISE.
NOW ON COURSE 98, MARK 12,
HEADING DIRECTLY TOWARD
GAMMA CANARUS REGION.
JIM, WE'VE GOT TO
GET MISS HEDFORD
BACK TO THE
ENTERPRISE.
HER CONDITION.
I KNOW, BONES,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO ABOUT IT.
I INSIST YOU MAKE
YOUR SCHEDULED RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE ENTERPRISE.
MISS HEDFORD,
WE'LL DO WHAT WE CAN,
WHEN WE CAN.
AT THE MOMENT,
WE'RE HELPLESS.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
SIT BACK
AND ENJOY THE RIDE.
[CAPTAIN KIRK]
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS THE GALILEO.
COME IN, PLEASE,
COME IN.
ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS THE GALILEO.
COME IN, PLEASE.
NO GOOD.
WE'RE NOT TRANSMITTING.
BONES?
OXYGEN-NITROGEN
ATMOSPHERE,
SOME KRYPTON,
ARGON, NEON,
TEMPERATURE,
75 DEGREES FAHRENHEIT.
PRACTICALLY IDENTICAL
TO EARTH ATMOSPHERE.
SPOCK?
GRAVITY IS
SIMILAR TO EARTH.
MOST UNUSUAL
IN VIEW OF ITS SIZE.
THE BULK OF THE BODY SEEMS
TO BE IRON AND NICKEL.
MORE THAN AN ASTEROID.
LIKE A SMALL PLANETOID,
I SHOULD SAY.
POSSIBLY A REMNANT
FROM A PLANET BREAKUP.
TOTALLY SUITABLE
FOR HUMAN LIFE.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL GET OUT
AND GET UNDER.
ISSUE PHASERS.
BONES, MAINTAIN
FULL ALERT.
COMMISSIONER,
IF YOU'LL STAY
INSIDE.
JUST HOW LONG AM
I SUPPOSED TO STAY
INSIDE, CAPTAIN?
THAT'S
A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
I WISH
I COULD ANSWER IT.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S GO.
TAKE A LOOK AROUND, BONES.
MOST UNUSUAL.
UNLIKELY.
IN FACT, CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SAY
QUITE IMPOSSIBLE.
NOTHING WRONG
AND NOTHING WORKS.
PRECISELY.
MUST BE A REASON.
OBVIOUSLY.
LET'S LOOK
A LITTLE FURTHER.
JIM, I JUST TOOK
A TRICORDING SWEEP,
AND I GOT THE
EXACT SAME READINGS,
ALMOST, AS SPOCK GOT
WHEN WE WERE
PULLED OFF COURSE.
THE IONIZED CLOUD.
I THINK SO, ONLY IT
READS HERE ON THE
SURFACE WITH US.
IT'S OFF IN THAT DIRECTION,
AND IT DOESN'T READ SOLID.
IT'S MORE UNSTABLE,
TENUOUS,
LIKE A COLLECTION
OF GASES.
HELLO!
FASCINATING.
BONES, GET
A PHYSIOLOGICAL
READING ON THAT,
WHATEVER IT IS.
HELLO!
ARE YOU REAL?
I MEAN, I'M NOT
IMAGINING YOU, AM I?
WE'RE REAL ENOUGH.
YOU SPEAK ENGLISH.
EARTH PEOPLE?
FROM THE FEDERATION.
THE F--
WELL, IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I'M COCHRANE.
I'VE BEEN MAROONED HERE
WHO KNOWS HOW LONG.
IF YOU ONLY KNEW
HOW GOOD IT IS
TO SEE YOU.
AND A WOMAN.
BEAUTIFUL ONE AT THAT.
I'M CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK,
COMMANDING
THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
THIS IS
MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
YOU'RE A VULCAN,
AREN'T YOU?
CORRECT.
CHIEF SURGEON
LEONARD McCOY.
DOCTOR.
PLEASURE.
OH, AND EXCUSE ME,
ASSISTANT FEDERATION
COMMISSIONER HEDFORD.
MA'AM.
YOU'RE FOOD
TO A STARVING MAN.
ALL OF YOU.
HEY, THAT'S A NICE SHIP.
SIMPLE AND CLEAN.
BEEN TRYING
TO GET HER
TO GO AGAIN?
WELL, FORGET IT.
IT WON'T WORK.
HE'S HUMAN, JIM.
EVERYTHING CHECKS OUT
PERFECTLY.
MR. COCHRANE.
WE WERE FORCED
OFF OUR COURSE
AND TAKEN HERE BY SOME FORCE
WE COULDN'T IDENTIFY.
WHICH SEEMS TO BE
ON THE SURFACE
OF THIS BODY
AT THE MOMENT.
WELL, I WOULDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THAT.
YOU SAY
WE'LL BE UNABLE
TO GET THE SHIP TO
FUNCTION AGAIN?
NOT A CHANCE. THERE'S
SOME SORT OF DAMPING
FIELD DOWN HERE.
POWER SYSTEMS DON'T WORK.
TAKE MY WORD FOR IT.
YOU DON'T MIND
IF WE CONTINUE
TO TRY?
GO RIGHT AHEAD.
YOU GOT PLENTY OF TIME.
WHAT ABOUT YOU, COCHRANE?
HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
MAROONED, I TOLD YOU.
LOOK, WE'LL HAVE
LOTS OF TIME
TO LEARN
ABOUT EACH OTHER.
I HAVE A SMALL PLACE
OVER THAT WAY--
ALL THE COMFORTS
OF HOME.
I CAN EVEN OFFER YOU
A HOT BATH.
HOW PERCEPTIVE OF YOU TO
NOTICE THAT I NEEDED ONE.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
MR. COCHRANE,
I'D LIKE A LITTLE MORE
THAN JUST A STATEMENT
THAT YOU WERE
MAROONED HERE.
IT'S A LONG WAY OFF
THE BEATEN PATH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S WHY I'M
SO GLAD TO SEE YOU.
LOOK, I'LL TELL YOU
EVERYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW,
BUT NOT HERE.
YOUR SHIP
IS SURE A BEAUTY.
YES, SHE IS.
YOU'VE BEEN
OUT OF CIRCULATION
QUITE A WHILE.
THE PRINCIPLES
MAY BE NEW TO YOU.
MR. SPOCK...
WHY DON'T YOU
EXPLAIN OUR METHODS
OF PROPULSION
TO MR. COCHRANE?
TALKS A LOT,
BUT HE DOESN'T SAY MUCH.
I'VE NOTICED
SOMETHING ELSE.
WHAT'S THAT?
HE LOOKS FAMILIAR.
FAMILIAR?
NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
HE DOES.
I CAN'T QUITE
PLACE HIM, BUT...
WHAT ABOUT
MISS HEDFORD?
NO TEMPERATURE YET,
BUT WE GOT TO
GET UNDER WAY SOON, JIM.
I GUARANTEE YOU,
IT WILL DEVELOP.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
TAKE COCHRANE UP
ON HIS OFFER.
YOU BUILT THIS,
MR. COCHRANE?
YES. I HAD
TOOLS AND SUPPLIES
LEFT OVER FROM MY CRASH.
NOT BAD.
NOT EARTH, OF COURSE,
BUT IT'S LIVABLE.
I GROW VEGETABLES
IN THE FIELDS OVER
THAT NEXT RIDGE.
COME ON IN.
ALL THE COMFORTS OF HOME
INDEED, MR. COCHRANE.
WHERE'D YOU GET
THE ANTIQUES?
WHAT, YOU MEAN
MY INSTRUMENTS?
I IMAGINE THINGS
HAVE CHANGED A LOT
SINCE I CRASHED.
NOT THAT MUCH.
MUST YOU KEEP IT
SO TERRIBLY HOT IN HERE?
TEMPERATURE'S
A CONSTANT 72 DEGREES.
LET ME GET YOU
SOMETHING COOL TO DRINK.
DO YOU FEEL HOT?
I FEEL INFURIATED,
DEEPLY PUT UPON,
AND ABSOLUTELY OUTRAGED.
IT WAS QUITE A HIKE HERE.
YOU'RE TIRED.
JUST TAKE IT EASY
FOR A WHILE.
I'LL REST LATER,
DOCTOR.
TEMPERATURE,
CAPTAIN.
FIRST SIGN.
YES, I KNOW.
IT MEANS WE'RE
RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
CAPTAIN,
DOCTOR.
WHAT WAS THAT?
WELL, SOMETIMES THE LIGHT
PLAYS TRICKS ON YOU.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED
WHAT I'VE IMAGINED
I'VE SEEN AROUND
HERE SOMETIMES.
WE IMAGINED NOTHING,
MR. COCHRANE.
THERE WAS AN ENTITY
OUT THERE,
AND I SUSPECT IT WAS
THE SAME ENTITY WHICH
BROUGHT US HERE.
PLEASE EXPLAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO EXPLAIN.
THANK YOU.
YOU'LL FIND I HAVE
A VERY LOW TOLERANCE LEVEL
WHERE THE SAFETY
OF MY PEOPLE
ARE CONCERNED.
WE FIND YOU OUT HERE,
WHERE NO HUMAN HAS
ANY BUSINESS BEING.
WE WERE VIRTUALLY HIJACKED
IN SPACE AND BROUGHT HERE.
NOW, I'M NOT
JUST REQUESTING AN
EXPLANATION, MISTER.
I'M DEMANDING ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT WAS THE COMPANION.
THE WHAT?
THAT'S WHAT I CALL IT.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
CAPTAIN, I DIDN'T
CRASH HERE.
I WAS BROUGHT HERE
IN MY DISABLED SHIP.
I WAS ALMOST DEAD.
THE COMPANION
SAVED MY LIFE.
YOU WERE INJURED?
I WAS DYING,
MR. SPOCK.
YOU SEEM PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT NOW.
WHAT WAS THE MATTER?
I WAS AN OLD MAN.
YOU WERE WHAT?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
HOW IT DID IT,
BUT THE COMPANION
REJUVENATED ME,
MADE ME YOUNG AGAIN,
LIKE I AM NOW.
I PREFER TO
RESERVE JUDGMENT
ON THAT PART
OF YOUR STORY, SIR.
MEANWHILE, WOULD YOU
PLEASE EXPLAIN EXACTLY
WHAT THIS COMPANION
OF YOURS IS?
I TOLD YOU,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
IT EXISTS, IT LIVES,
AND I CAN
COMMUNICATE WITH IT.
THAT'S A PRETTY
FAR-OUT STORY.
MR. COCHRANE...
DO YOU HAVE
A FIRST NAME?
ZEFRAM.
ZEFRAM COCHRANE...
OF ALPHA CENTURI...
THE DISCOVERER
OF THE SPACE WARP?
THAT'S RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
BUT THAT'S
IMPOSSIBLE.
ZEFRAM COCHRANE DIED
150 YEARS AGO.
[SPOCK]
THE NAME OF
ZEFRAM COCHRANE
IS REVERED THROUGHOUT
THE KNOWN GALAXY.
PLANETS WERE
NAMED AFTER HIM.
GREAT UNIVERSITIES,
CITIES.
ISN'T YOUR STORY
A LITTLE IMPROBABLE,
MR. COCHRANE?
NO, IT'S TRUE. I WAS 87
YEARS OLD WHEN I CAME HERE.
YOU SAY
THIS...COMPANION
FOUND YOU
AND REJUVENATED YOU?
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
IN SPACE AT
THE AGE OF 87?
I WAS TIRED, CAPTAIN.
I WAS GONNA DIE, AND
I WANTED TO DIE IN SPACE,
THAT'S ALL.
TRUE. HIS BODY
WAS NEVER FOUND.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT,
MR. SPOCK.
IF SO, YOU WEAR YOUR AGE
VERY WELL.
[DR. McCOY]
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
TERRIBLE.
HOW SHOULD I FEEL?
YOU'RE RUNNING
A LITTLE TEMPERATURE.
PERHAPS
YOU SHOULD LIE DOWN.
DOCTOR, WILL YOU PLEASE
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE?
IT'S THE HEAT.
ALL RIGHT.
TRY TO RELAX.
JIM...
IT'S STARTED,
THE FEVER.
IT'S OVER 100,
AND IT'S CLIMBING.
HOW LONG DO WE HAVE?
A MATTER OF HOURS,
THAT'S ALL.
MR. COCHRANE, YOU SAY
YOU WERE BROUGHT HERE
150 YEARS AGO?
YOU DON'T LOOK A DAY
OVER 35.
I HAVEN'T AGED.
THE COMPANION SEES TO THAT.
CAPTAIN...
THESE INSTRUMENTS,
THEY DATE FROM
THE TIME INDICATED.
FROM YOUR SHIP,
MR. COCHRANE?
I CANNIBALIZED IT.
THE FOOD, WATER, GARDENS,
EVERYTHING ELSE I NEED,
THE COMPANION GIVES ME.
APPARENTLY, IT CREATES IT
OUT OF THE NATIVE ELEMENTS.
YOU SAY YOU CAN
COMMUNICATE WITH IT.
PERHAPS YOU CAN FIND OUT
WHAT WE'RE DOING HERE.
I ALREADY KNOW.
YOU WOULDN'T MIND
TELLING US?
YOU WON'T LIKE IT.
I ALREADY
DON'T LIKE IT.
YOU'RE HERE
TO KEEP ME COMPANY.
YOU MEAN
YOU BROUGHT US HERE?
NO. THE COMPANION DID.
I TOLD IT
I'D DIE OF LONELINESS.
I THOUGHT
IT WOULD RELEASE ME.
INSTEAD,
IT BROUGHT YOU HERE.
NO!
THAT'S DISGUSTING!
WE'RE NOT ANIMALS!
NO!
OH, NO!
IT'S INHUMAN!
NO!
SPOCK, RUN ADDITIONAL
TRICORDER READINGS.
LEARN ANYTHING YOU CAN.
FIND ME A WEAPON TO
USE AGAINST THIS THING.
YOU ASK ME TO
FIND A WEAPON?
DO YOU INTEND
TO DESTROY IT?
I INTEND TO DO
WHATEVER'S NECESSARY
TO GET US
OFF THIS PLANET
AND COMMISSIONER HEDFORD
TO THE HOSPITAL.
IF THE COMPANION
STANDS IN THE WAY,
THEN WE PUSH IT
OUT OF THE WAY.
CLEAR, SPOCK?
QUITE CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
VERY WELL.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
MR. COCHRANE,
IF YOU LEFT HERE,
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO YOU?
I'D BEGIN TO AGE AGAIN--
NORMALLY.
DO YOU WANT
TO LEAVE HERE?
BELIEVE ME, CAPTAIN,
IMMORTALITY CONSISTS
LARGELY OF BOREDOM.
WHAT'S IT LIKE
OUT THERE IN THE GALAXY?
WE'RE ON 1,000 PLANETS
AND SPREADING OUT.
WE CROSS
FANTASTIC DISTANCES,
AND EVERYTHING'S ALIVE,
COCHRANE.
LIFE EVERYWHERE.
WE ESTIMATE THERE ARE
MILLIONS OF PLANETS
WITH INTELLIGENT LIFE.
WE HAVEN'T BEGUN
TO MAP THEM.
INTERESTING?
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO
GO TO SLEEP FOR 150 YEARS
AND WAKE UP
IN A NEW WORLD?
IT'S ALL OUT THERE
WAITING FOR YOU.
BUT WE'LL NEED YOUR
HELP TO GET AWAY.
YOU'VE GOT IT.
[THUNDERBOLT]
YOU SEEM TO THINK
THIS COMPANION OF YOURS
CAN DO ALMOST ANYTHING.
I SAID
IT WAS VERY POWERFUL.
COULD IT CURE HER?
I DON'T KNOW.
HOW DO YOU
COMMUNICATE WITH IT?
IT'S ON A NONVERBAL LEVEL,
BUT I USUALLY GET
MY MESSAGE ACROSS.
WE'VE GOT TO TRY.
WE'RE HELPLESS.
SEE IF IT CAN
DO SOMETHING.
HOW DO YOU DO IT?
I JUST SORT OF
CLEAR MY MIND,
AND IT COMES.
BONES, WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF THAT?
ALMOST A SYMBIOSIS
OF SOME KIND,
SORT OF JOINING.
EXACTLY WHAT I THINK.
NOT EXACTLY
LIKE A PET OWNER
SPEAKING TO
A BELOVED ANIMAL,
WOULDN'T YOU SAY?
NO.
IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
AGREED.
MORE LIKE...
LOVE.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
IT KIND OF DRAINS ME
A LITTLE, BUT I'M
ALL RIGHT.
WELL?
THE COMPANION
CAN'T DO ANYTHING
TO HELP MISS HEDFORD.
THEN SHE'LL DIE.
IF THERE'S ANYTHING
I COULD DO TO HELP,
I WOULD, AND I WILL,
BUT WE CAN EXPECT NOTHING
FROM THE COMPANION.
SPOCK!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
QUITE ALL RIGHT,
DOCTOR.
A MOST FASCINATING
THING HAPPENED.
APPARENTLY,
THE COMPANION
IMPARTED TO ME
A RATHER QUAINT,
OLD-FASHIONED
ELECTRIC SHOCK
OF RESPECTABLE
VOLTAGE.
IT ATTACKED YOU?
EVIDENTLY.
UNQUESTIONABLY,
A LARGE PART OF
ITS SUBSTANCE
IS SIMPLE
ELECTRICITY.
OH, YES.
I'M NOT A SCIENTIST
OR A PHYSICIST,
MR. SPOCK,
BUT AM I CORRECT
IN ASSUMING
THAT ANYTHING THAT
GENERATES ELECTRICITY
CAN BE SHORTED OUT?
QUITE CORRECT, DOCTOR.
PUT THIS
IN THE PROXIMITY
OF THE COMPANION,
THROW THIS SWITCH,
AND IT WILL
SCRAMBLE EVERY
ELECTRICAL IMPULSE
THE CREATURE
CAN PRODUCE.
IT CANNOT FAIL.
IT TROUBLES YOU,
COCHRANE?
THE COMPANION
SAVED MY LIFE.
IT'S TAKEN CARE OF ME
ALL THESE YEARS.
WE'VE BEEN VERY CLOSE
IN A WAY
THAT'S HARD TO EXPLAIN.
I SUPPOSE I EVEN HAVE
A SORT OF AFFECTION
FOR IT.
IT'S ALSO
KEEPING YOU PRISONER.
I DON'T WANT IT
KILLED.
IT MAY SIMPLY
RENDER IT POWERLESS.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW.
YOU COULD KILL IT.
I WON'T STAND FOR THAT,
KIRK.
WE'RE GETTING OUT
OF HERE, COCHRANE.
FACE UP TO IT.
I'LL DO ANYTHING I HAVE TO
TO SAVE ALL OF OUR LIVES.
I SUPPOSE FROM
YOUR POINT OF VIEW,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU FEEL,
MR. COCHRANE,
BUT IT HAS TO BE DONE.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU WANT ME
TO CONTACT IT?
PLEASE.
OUTSIDE.
WHAT WAS IT
THEY USED TO CALL IT,
THE JUDAS GOAT?
THERE IS SOME RISK,
CAPTAIN.
WE DO NOT KNOW
THE EXTENT
OF ITS POWERS.
NOR IT OURS.
NOW.
STOP IT!
YOU'RE KILLING THEM!
STOP IT, PLEASE!
STOP IT!
YOU'RE CHOKING THEM!
LET THEM GO.
STOP IT!
YOU ALL RIGHT, JIM?
YEAH,
WE'RE ALL RIGHT.
COCHRANE GOT IT
OFF OF US.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
HE DID US A FAVOR
OR NOT.
WHAT KIND OF TALK
IS THAT?
HOW DO YOU FIGHT
A THING LIKE THAT?
I'VE GOT THE SHIP
UP THERE SOMEWHERE,
RESPONSIBILITY FOR
FOUR LIVES DOWN HERE--
ONE OF THEM DYING
BECAUSE OF ME.
IT ISN'T YOUR FAULT.
I'M IN COMMAND, BONES.
IT MAKES IT MY FAULT.
HOW DO YOU FIGHT
A THING LIKE THAT?
MAYBE YOU'RE
A SOLDIER SO OFTEN
THAT YOU FORGET
YOU'RE ALSO TRAINED
TO BE A DIPLOMAT.
WHY NOT TRY A CARROT
INSTEAD OF A STICK?
SPOCK.
YES, CAPTAIN?
THE UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR
ON THE SHUTTLECRAFT--
WE CAN TRY THAT,
TALK TO THAT THING.
THE TRANSLATOR IS FOR
USE WITH MORE CONGRUENT
LIFE FORMS.
ADJUST IT.
CHANGE IT.
THE TROUBLE WITH
IMMORTALITY
IS IT'S BORING.
ADJUSTING
THE TRANSLATOR
WILL GIVE YOU
SOMETHING TO DO.
IT'S POSSIBLE.
IF I COULD WIDEN ITS
PATTERN OF RECEPTION--
RIGHT DOWN YOUR
ALLEY, SPOCK.
GET IT HERE
AND GET TO WORK.
AND THAT THING
IS STILL
OUT THERE.
BETTER
GO THAT WAY.
ANY CHANGE?
YES, FOR THE WORSE.
SHIP'S LOG.
STARDATE 3219.8.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER SCOTT
RECORDING IN THE ABSENCE
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
A SHUTTLECRAFT BEARING THE
CAPTAIN, THE FIRST OFFICER,
CHIEF SURGEON McCOY,
AND ASSISTANT FEDERATION
COMMISSIONER HEDFORD
IS NOW
DEFINITELY OVERDUE
FOR A RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE ENTERPRISE.
WE ARE ATTEMPTING
TO BACKTRACK IT.
[UHURA]
MR. SCOTT.
COMPUTER CENTRAL REPORTS
THAT WE'RE COMING UP
ON THE COORDINATES
OF THE LAST ESTABLISHED
POSITION OF THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
[SULU]
STEADY.
NO. MR. SCOTT,
BEARING 310, MARK 35
JUST CLEARED.
NO ANTIMATTER RESIDUE.
ALL SCANNERS--
SPHERICAL SWEEP.
RANGE--MAXIMUM.
THEY'LL HAVE TO
PICK IT UP.
IF THE SHUTTLECRAFT
POWERED AWAY, MR. SCOTT.
BUT IF IT WERE JUST
TOWED?
THERE WOULD STILL
BE TRACES OF RESIDUAL
MATTER
FLOATING AROUND,
LIEUTENANT.
BEARING 210,
MARK 40.
STRONG PARTICLE
CONCENTRATION.
WE'RE ON IT,
MR. SCOTT.
LAY ON THAT COURSE.
MAINTAIN SCANNING.
COURSE LAID IN, SIR.
[BEEPING--DESCENDING
MUSICAL NOTES]
PARTICLE DENSITY
DECREASING.
GONE, SIR.
NO READINGS.
STEADY AS SHE GOES,
MR. SULU.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
IT MEANS, MR. SCOTT?
THE SHUTTLECRAFT
WAS ON SCHEDULE
UNTIL IT WAS SHY
5 HOURS OF RENDEZVOUS.
THEN SOMETHING
HAPPENED.
WELL, I'D FEEL
A LOT BETTER
IF YOU WERE A LITTLE
MORE DEFINITE.
IT DIDN'T WRECK.
THERE WAS NO DEBRIS.
THERE'S NO TRACE OF
EXPELLED INTERNAL ATMOSPHERE,
NO RESIDUAL RADIOACTIVITY.
AH, IT'S...
SOMETHING TOOK OVER--
TRACTOR BEAMS MAYBE--
SOMETHING.
THEY DRAGGED IT AWAY
ON THE HEADING WE'RE NOW ON.
IF THERE ARE
NO FURTHER TRACES,
HOW ARE WE GOING
TO FOLLOW THEM?
WE STAY ON THIS COURSE,
SEE WHAT COMES UP.
IT'S A BIG GALAXY,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE.
WHAT'S THE THEORY
BEHIND THIS DEVICE?
THERE ARE CERTAIN UNIVERSAL
IDEAS AND CONCEPTS
COMMON TO ALL
INTELLIGENT LIFE.
THIS DEVICE
INSTANTANEOUSLY COMPARES
THE FREQUENCY
OF BRAIN-WAVE PATTERNS,
SELECTS THOSE IDEAS
AND CONCEPTS IT RECOGNIZES,
AND THEN PROVIDES
THE NECESSARY GRAMMAR.
THEN IT SIMPLY
TRANSLATES ITS
FINDINGS
INTO ENGLISH.
YOU MEAN IT SPEAKS?
WITH A VOICE
OR THE APPROXIMATION
OF WHATEVER THE CREATURE IS
ON THE SENDING END.
NOT 100% EFFICIENT,
OF COURSE, BUT
NOTHING EVER IS.
READY, MR. SPOCK?
QUITE READY,
CAPTAIN.
MR. COCHRANE,
CALL THE COMPANION.
COMPANION.
WE WISH
TO TALK TO YOU.
[FEMININE VOICE]
HOW CAN WE COMMUNICATE?
MY THOUGHTS...
YOU ARE HEARING THEM.
THIS IS INTERESTING.
FEMININE. NO DOUBT
ABOUT IT, SPOCK.
YES. THE MATTER OF GENDER
COULD CHANGE
THE ENTIRE SITUATION.
I'M WAY
AHEAD OF YOU.
THEN IT IS NOT
A ZOOKEEPER.
NO.
A LOVER.
COMPANION...
IT IS WRONG TO KEEP US
HERE AGAINST OUR WILL.
THE MAN NEEDS THE COMPANY
OF HIS OWN KIND,
OR HE WILL
CEASE TO EXIST.
HE FELT IT TO ME.
ONE OF US WILL
CEASE TO EXIST
IF WE DON'T GET HER
TO A PLACE
WHERE WE CAN
CARE FOR HER.
THE MAN NEEDS
OTHERS OF HIS SPECIES.
THAT IS WHY
YOU ARE HERE.
THE MAN MUST CONTINUE.
COMPANION...
TRY TO UNDERSTAND.
IT IS THE NATURE OF
OUR SPECIES TO BE FREE,
JUST AS IT IS YOUR
NATURE TO STAY HERE.
WE WILL...CEASE TO EXIST
IN CAPTIVITY.
YOUR BODIES
HAVE STOPPED
THEIR PECULIAR
DEGENERATION.
THERE WILL BE NOTHING
TO HARM YOU.
YOU WILL CONTINUE,
AND THE MAN
WILL CONTINUE.
THIS IS NECESSARY.
THIS IS A MARVELOUS
OPPORTUNITY TO ADD
TO OUR KNOWLEDGE.
ASK IT ABOUT
ITS NATURE, ITS HISTORY.
SPOCK, THIS ISN'T
A CLASSROOM.
I'M TRYING TO GET
US OUT OF HERE.
A CHANCE LIKE THIS
MAY NEVER COME AGAIN.
IT COULD TELL US
SO MUCH.
THIS ISN'T THE TIME.
COMPANION,
WHAT YOU OFFER US
IS NOT CONTINUATION.
IT IS NON-EXISTENCE.
WE WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
EVEN THE MAN
WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
YOUR IMPULSES
ARE ILLOGICAL.
THIS COMMUNICATION
IS USELESS.
THE MAN MUST CONTINUE.
THEREFORE,
YOU WILL CONTINUE.
IT IS NECESSARY.
CAPTAIN...
WHY DID YOU BUILD
THAT TRANSLATOR
WITH A FEMININE
VOICE?
WE DIDN'T.
BUT I HEARD--
THE IDEA OF MALE
AND FEMALE ARE UNIVERSAL
CONSTANTS, COCHRANE.
THERE'S NO DOUBT ABOUT IT--
THE COMPANION IS FEMALE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU DON'T?
A BLIND MAN COULD
SEE IT WITH A CANE.
YOU'RE NOT A PET.
YOU'RE NOT A SPECIMEN
KEPT IN A CAGE.
YOU'RE A LOVER.
I'M A WHAT?
HER ATTITUDE
WHEN SHE APPROACHES YOU
IS PROFOUNDLY DIFFERENT
THAN WHEN SHE CONTACTS US.
HER APPEARANCE IS
SOFT, GENTLE.
HER VOICE IS
MELODIC, PLEASING.
I DO NOT TOTALLY
UNDERSTAND THE EMOTION,
BUT IT OBVIOUSLY
EXISTS.
THE COMPANION LOVES YOU.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING?
FOR ALL THESE YEARS,
I'VE LET SOMETHING
AS ALIEN AS THAT
CRAWL AROUND
INSIDE ME,
INTO MY MIND,
MY FEELINGS?
WHAT ARE YOU
COMPLAINING ABOUT?
IT KEPT YOU ALIVE,
DIDN'T IT?
THAT THING FED
ON ME, USED ME.
IT'S DISGUSTING.
THERE'S NOTHING
DISGUSTING ABOUT IT.
IT'S JUST ANOTHER
LIFE FORM, THAT'S ALL.
YOU GET USED
TO THOSE THINGS.
YOU'RE AS BAD
AS IT IS.
YOUR HIGHLY EMOTIONAL
REACTION IS MOST ILLOGICAL.
YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH THE COMPANION
HAS FOR 150 YEARS BEEN
EMOTIONALLY SATISFYING,
EMINENTLY PRACTICAL,
AND TOTALLY HARMLESS.
IT MAY, INDEED, HAVE
BEEN QUITE BENEFICIAL.
IS THIS
WHAT THE FUTURE HOLDS,
MEN WHO HAVE NO NOTION
OF DECENCY OR MORALITY?
MAYBE I'M 150 YEARS
OUT OF STYLE,
BUT I'M NOT
GOING TO BE FODDER
FOR ANY
INHUMAN MONSTER.
FASCINATING--
A TOTALLY
PAROCHIAL ATTITUDE.
DOCTOR?
DOCTOR.
RIGHT HERE,
MISS HEDFORD.
I HEARD HIM.
HE WAS LOVED...
AND HE RESENTS IT.
YOU JUST REST.
NO.
I--I DON'T
WANT TO DIE.
I'VE BEEN--BEEN
GOOD AT MY JOB...
BUT...
I'VE NEVER
BEEN LOVED.
NEVER.
WH-WHAT KIND OF LIFE
IS THAT...
NOT TO BE LOVED...
NEVER...
TO HAVE SHOWN LOVE?
AND HE RUNS
AWAY FROM LOVE.
[SOBS]
SHIP'S LOG,
STARDATE 3220.3.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER SCOTT
REPORTING
IN LIEU OF THE CAPTAIN
AND THE FIRST OFFICER.
WE ARE CONTINUING
OUR SEARCH
FOR THE MISSING
SHUTTLECRAFT.
APPROACHING WHAT SEEMS
TO BE AN ASTEROID BELT, SIR.
SCANNERS REPORT
APPROXIMATELY 7,000 BODIES
OF SIZES RUNNING
FROM TYPES "A" TO "N."
ATMOSPHERE COUNT?
APPROXIMATELY 34%
OF THE BODIES
OF ATMOSPHERIAN TYPES
"H" TO "M."
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
WE'LL DO IT THE HARD WAY.
ALL SENSORS SET FOR
LIFE FORM REGISTRATION--
AUTOMATIC SELECTION.
MR. SCOTT,
THERE ARE THOUSANDS
OF THEM OUT THERE
THEY COULD BE ON,
IF THEY'RE ON ANY
OF THEM AT ALL.
AYE, THAT'S RIGHT,
LIEUTENANT.
THOUSANDS...
AND WE'LL LOOK THEM OVER
ONE BY ONE.
COMPANION,
DO YOU LOVE THE MAN?
I...
DO NOT...
UNDERSTAND.
IS HE IMPORTANT TO YOU,
MORE IMPORTANT
THAN ANYTHING?
IS HE...
AS THOUGH HE
WERE A PART OF YOU?
HE IS PART OF ME.
THE MAN MUST CONTINUE.
HE WILL NOT CONTINUE.
HE WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
BY YOUR FEELING FOR HIM,
YOU ARE CONDEMNING HIM
TO AN EXISTENCE
HE WILL FIND UNBEARABLE.
HE WILL CEASE TO EXIST.
HE DOES NOT AGE.
HE REMAINS FOREVER.
YOU SPEAK OF HIS BODY.
I SPEAK OF HIS SPIRIT.
COMPANION,
INSIDE THE SHELTER,
A FEMALE OF OUR SPECIES
IS DYING.
SHE WILL NOT CONTINUE.
THAT IS WHAT
WILL HAPPEN TO THE MAN
UNLESS YOU RELEASE
ALL OF US.
I...
DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
OUR SPECIES...
CAN ONLY SURVIVE...
IF WE HAVE OBSTACLES
TO OVERCOME.
YOU...
TAKE AWAY ALL OBSTACLES.
WITHOUT THEM
TO STRENGTHEN US,
WE WILL WEAKEN AND DIE.
YOU REGARD THE MAN
ONLY AS A TOY.
YOU AMUSE YOURSELF
WITH HIM.
YOU ARE WRONG.
THE MAN IS THE CENTER
OF ALL THINGS.
I CARE FOR HIM.
BUT YOU CAN'T
REALLY LOVE HIM.
YOU HAVEN'T THE SLIGHTEST
KNOWLEDGE OF LOVE,
THE TOTAL UNION
OF TWO PEOPLE.
YOU ARE THE COMPANION.
HE IS THE MAN.
YOU ARE
TWO DIFFERENT THINGS.
YOU CAN'T JOIN.
YOU CAN'T...
LOVE.
YOU MAY KEEP HIM HERE
FOREVER...
BUT YOU WILL ALWAYS
BE SEPARATE...
APART FROM HIM.
IF...
I WERE HUMAN...
THERE CAN BE...
LOVE?
WHAT DID YOU HOPE
TO GAIN BY THAT, JIM?
TRY TO CONVINCE HER
OF THE HOPELESSNESS
OF IT.
LOVE SOMETIMES
EXPRESSES ITSELF
IN SACRIFICE.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
IF SHE LOVED HIM,
SHE'D LET HIM GO.
BUT SHE OR IT
IS INHUMAN, CAPTAIN.
YOU CANNOT EXPECT HER
TO REACT LIKE A HUMAN.
I TRIED.
IT'S USELESS.
I KNOW.
ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
BONES?
I DON'T
UNDERSTAND IT.
SHE'S NOT SICK
AT ALL.
WE UNDERSTAND.
IT'S HER.
WHAT?
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT'S THE COMPANION.
BONES?
SHE'S PERFECTLY
HEALTHY.
HEART LIKE A HAMMER.
RESPIRATION NORMAL.
BLOOD PRESSURE
NORMAL.
THIS IS MEDICALLY
IMPOSSIBLE.
WE ARE HERE.
WE?
BOTH OF US--
THOSE YOU KNEW
AS THE COMMISSIONER
AND THE COMPANION.
WE ARE BOTH HERE.
COMPANION,
YOU DO NOT HAVE THE POWER
TO CREATE LIFE.
THAT IS FOR THE MAKER
OF ALL THINGS.
BUT COMMISSIONER HEDFORD
WAS DYING.
THAT PART OF US
WAS TOO WEAK
TO HOLD ON.
IN A MOMENT, THERE WOULD
HAVE BEEN NO CONTINUING.
NOW WE'RE TOGETHER.
THEN YOU ARE BOTH HERE,
IN THE ONE BODY?
WE ARE ONE.
ZEFRAM...
WE FRIGHTEN YOU.
WE'VE NEVER
FRIGHTENED YOU BEFORE.
LONELINESS.
THIS IS LONELINESS.
OH, WHAT A BITTER THING.
OH, ZEFRAM,
IT'S SO SAD.
HOW DO YOU BEAR IT,
THIS LONELINESS?
SPOCK, CHECK OUT
THE SHUTTLECRAFT--
ENGINE, COMMUNICATIONS,
EVERYTHING.
THAT WILL NOT
BE NECESSARY, CAPTAIN.
YOUR VEHICLE WILL OPERATE
AS BEFORE.
SO WILL
THE COMMUNICATIONS DEVICE.
YOU'RE LETTING US GO?
WE COULD DO NOTHING NOW
TO STOP YOU.
YOU SAID WE
WOULD NOT KNOW LOVE
BECAUSE WE WERE NOT HUMAN.
NOW WE ARE HUMAN.
WE'LL KNOW
THE CHANGE OF THE DAYS.
WE WILL KNOW DEATH.
BUT TO TOUCH
THE HAND OF THE MAN,
NOTHING IS AS IMPORTANT.
YOU'RE VERY BEAUTIFUL.
PART OF ME...
UNDERSTANDS.
PART DOES NOT.
BUT IT PLEASES ME.
I COULD EXPLAIN...
MANY THINGS.
OH, LET ME WALK, ZEFRAM.
LET ME FEEL THE EARTH
AGAINST MY FEET.
LET ME FEEL THE WARMTH
OF THE SUN ON MY FACE.
YOU BESIDE ME--
LET ME
FEEL THESE THINGS.
GO AHEAD, COCHRANE.
WE HAVE A FEW THINGS TO DO.
MR. SCOTT,
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
PUT HIM ON.
LOCK ON TO
HIS COORDINATES.
CAPTAIN, THIS IS SCOTTY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
PERFECTLY ALL RIGHT.
CAN YOU GET A FIX ON US?
THE HELM IS COMPUTING
YOUR POSITION NOW, CAPTAIN.
COURSE 224, MARK 12.
E.T.A. 57 MINUTES.
WE'LL BE THERE
IN 57 MINUTES, SIR.
VERY GOOD. I'LL CONTINUE
TRANSMITTING.
ASSUME STANDARD ORBIT
WHEN YOU ARRIVE.
WE'LL TRANSPORT UP
IN THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
WHAT HAPPENED, CAPTAIN?
INTERESTING STORY, SCOTTY.
I CAN'T TELL YOU NOW
BECAUSE, QUITE FRANKLY,
I DON'T KNOW HOW
IT'S GOING TO END.
KIRK OUT.
EVERYTHING WILL BE
AN EYE-OPENER TO YOU.
THERE'S A THOUSAND
PLANETS OUT THERE,
A THOUSAND RACES.
I'LL SHOW EVERYTHING TO YOU,
SOON AS I LEARN
MY WAY AROUND AGAIN.
MAYBE I CAN MAKE UP
A LITTLE FOR EVERYTHING
YOU'VE DONE FOR ME.
I CAN'T GO WITH YOU,
ZEFRAM.
OF COURSE YOU CAN.
YOU HAVE TO.
MY LIFE EMANATES
FROM THIS PLACE.
IF I SHOULD LEAVE IT
FOR MORE THAN
A TINY MARCH OF DAYS,
I'LL CEASE TO EXIST.
I MUST RETURN, EVEN AS
YOU MUST CONSUME MATTER
TO MAINTAIN YOUR LIFE.
YOU MEAN YOU GAVE UP
EVERYTHING TO BE HUMAN?
BUT EVEN IF YOU STAY HERE,
YOU'LL EVENTUALLY DIE.
THE JOY OF THIS HOUR...
I AM PLEASED.
I CAN'T JUST FLY AWAY
AND LEAVE YOU HERE.
YOU MUST BE FREE,
ZEFRAM COCHRANE.
YOU SAVED MY LIFE...
TOOK CARE OF ME.
YOU LOVED ME.
I NEVER UNDERSTOOD.
I DO NOW.
WE'RE LOCKED IN, CAPTAIN.
STANDARD ORBIT ESTABLISHED.
SHUTTLECRAFT BAY STANDING
BY TO RECEIVE YOU.
STAND BY, SCOTTY.
THE ENTERPRISE IS
WAITING, MR. COCHRANE.
I CAN'T TAKE HER
AWAY FROM HERE.
IF I DO, SHE'LL DIE.
IF I LEAVE HER,
SHE'LL DIE OF LONELINESS.
I OWE EVERYTHING TO HER.
I CAN'T LEAVE HER.
I LOVE HER.
IS THAT SURPRISING?
NOT COMING
FROM A HUMAN BEING.
YOU ARE, AFTER ALL,
ESSENTIALLY IRRATIONAL.
THINK IT OVER,
MR. COCHRANE.
THERE'S A WHOLE
GALAXY OUT THERE
WAITING
TO HONOR YOU.
I HAVE HONORS ENOUGH.
BUT YOU WILL AGE,
BOTH OF YOU.
THERE WILL BE
NO IMMORTALITY.
YOU'LL BOTH
GROW OLD HERE...
AND FINALLY DIE.
THAT'S BEEN HAPPENED TO
MEN AND WOMEN FOR A LONG TIME.
I'VE GOT THE FEELING IT'S
ONE OF THE PLEASANTER THINGS
ABOUT BEING HUMAN,
AS LONG AS
YOU GROW OLD TOGETHER.
ARE YOU SURE?
THERE'S PLENTY
OF WATER HERE.
THE CLIMATE'S GOOD
FOR GROWING THINGS.
I MIGHT EVEN TRY
AND PLANT A FIG TREE.
A MAN'S ENTITLED
TO THAT, ISN'T HE?
IT ISN'T GRATITUDE,
CAPTAIN.
NOW THAT I SEE HER...
TOUCH HER...
I KNOW THAT I LOVE HER.
WE'LL HAVE A LOT
OF YEARS TOGETHER.
THEY'LL BE HAPPY ONES.
ALL THE BEST.
CAPTAIN...
DON'T TELL THEM ABOUT ME.
NOT A WORD,
MR. COCHRANE.
JIM, WHAT ABOUT THAT WAR
ON EPSILON CANARUS 3?
WELL, I'M SURE
THE FEDERATION
CAN FIND ANOTHER WOMAN
SOMEWHERE
WHO'LL STOP THAT WAR.