DRESS UNIFORMS,
SPIT AND POLISH.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW MUCH LONGER
I'M GOING TO BE
ABLE TO STAND
THIS.
I FEEL LIKE
MY NECK'S
IN A SLING.
THE VULCANS
ARE THE LAST DELEGATES
WE HAVE TO PICK UP.
AS SOON AS WE GET THEM
ABOARD, WE'LL BE ABLE TO RELAX.
SURE. A FORMAL
RECEPTION TONIGHT,
114 DELEGATES ABOARD
FOR TWO WEEKS,
32 OF THEM
AMBASSADORS,
HALF OF THEM MAD
AT THE OTHER HALF,
[BEEP]
AND THE WHOLE LOT
TOUCHIER THAN A RAW
ANTIMATTER PILE
OVER THIS
CORIDAN QUESTION.
KIRK HERE.
[CHEKOV]
SHUTTLECRAFT APPROACHING
WITH AMBASSADOR SAREK'S
PARTY--ESTIMATE ARRIVAL,
ONE MINUTE.
BRING THEM ABOARD,
MR. CHEKOV.
[CHEKOV] STAND BY
TO RECOVER SHUTTLECRAFT.
HONOR GUARD
TO THE HANGAR DECK.
[TECHNICIAN]
CLEAR HANGAR DECK.
DEPRESSURIZING.
RECOVERING SHUTTLECRAFT.
HANGAR DECK PRESSURIZING.
HOW DOES THAT
VULCAN SALUTE GO?
THAT HURTS WORSE
THAN THE UNIFORM.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
CAPTAIN.
MY FIRST OFFICER,
COMMANDER SPOCK.
VULCAN HONORS US
WITH YOUR PRESENCE.
WE COME TO SERVE.
YOUR SERVICE HONORS US,
CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER
DR. McCOY.
AMBASSADOR.
DOCTOR.
MY AIDES
AND SHE WHO IS
MY WIFE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
OUR PLEASURE, MADAM.
SOON AS YOU'RE SETTLED,
I'LL ARRANGE A TOUR
OF THE SHIP.
MR. SPOCK WILL CONDUCT YOU.
I PREFER ANOTHER GUIDE,
CAPTAIN.
AS YOU WISH, AMBASSADOR.
MR. SPOCK, WE'LL LEAVE ORBIT
IN TWO HOURS.
WOULD YOU CARE TO BEAM DOWN
AND VISIT YOUR PARENTS?
CAPTAIN,
AMBASSADOR SAREK
AND HIS WIFE
ARE MY PARENTS.
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3842.3.
WE HAVE DEPARTED VULCAN
FOR THE NEUTRAL PLANETOID
CODE-NAMED BABEL.
SINCE IT IS IN OUR SECTOR,
THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN ASSIGNED
TO TRANSPORT AMBASSADORS
OF FEDERATION PLANETS
TO THIS VITALLY IMPORTANT
COUNCIL.
THE ISSUES OF THE COUNCIL
ARE POLITICALLY COMPLEX,
THE PASSENGERS...
EXPLOSIVE.
THIS IS THE
ENGINEERING SECTION.
THERE ARE A NUMBER
OF EMERGENCY
BACKUP SYSTEMS
FOR
THE MAIN CONTROLS.
OVER HERE ARE
A NUMBER OF
CONTROL COMPUTERS.
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS
AMONG HUMANS,
YOU STILL HAVEN'T
LEARNED TO SMILE.
HUMANS SMILE
WITH SO LITTLE PROVOCATION.
AND YOU HAVEN'T
COME TO SEE US
IN FOUR YEARS, EITHER.
THE SITUATION
BETWEEN MY FATHER
AND MYSELF
HAS NOT CHANGED.
MY WIFE, ATTEND.
MR. SPOCK.
A MOMENT,
IF YOU PLEASE.
YES, CAPTAIN?
EXPLAIN THE COMPUTER
COMPONENTS.
I GAVE SPOCK
HIS FIRST INSTRUCTION
IN COMPUTERS, CAPTAIN.
HE CHOSE TO DEVOTE
HIS KNOWLEDGE TO STARFLEET
INSTEAD OF
THE VULCAN SCIENCE ACADEMY.
IF YOU WILL EXCUSE
ME, CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY,
AMBASSADOR.
I DID NOT MEAN
TO OFFEND.
I THOUGHT THAT--
OFFENSE
IS A HUMAN EMOTION.
I'M RETURNING
TO MY QUARTERS.
CONTINUE, MY WIFE.
MRS. SAREK,
I JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND.
AMANDA.
I'M AFRAID YOU
COULDN'T PRONOUNCE
THE VULCAN NAME.
CAN YOU?
AFTER A FASHION,
AND AFTER MANY
YEARS OF PRACTICE.
SHALL WE
CONTINUE THE TOUR?
MY HUSBAND
DID REQUEST IT.
IT SOUNDED MORE
LIKE A COMMAND.
OF COURSE.
HE'S A VULCAN.
I'M HIS WIFE.
AND SPOCK IS HIS SON.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE VULCAN WAY, CAPTAIN.
IT'S LOGICAL.
IT'S A BETTER WAY
THAN OURS.
BUT IT'S NOT EASY.
IT HAS KEPT
SPOCK AND SAREK
FROM SPEAKING
AS FATHER AND SON
FOR 18 YEARS.
SPOCK IS MY BEST OFFICER...
AND MY FRIEND.
I'M GLAD HE HAS
SUCH A FRIEND.
IT HASN'T BEEN
EASY ON SPOCK.
NEITHER HUMAN
NOR VULCAN.
AT HOME NOWHERE
EXCEPT STARFLEET.
I TAKE IT THAT SPOCK
DISAGREED WITH HIS FATHER
ON A CHOICE OF CAREER.
MY HUSBAND HAS NOTHING
AGAINST STARFLEET.
BUT VULCANS BELIEVE
THAT PEACE SHOULD NOT
DEPEND ON FORCE.
STARFLEET FORCE
IS USED ONLY AS
A LAST RESORT.
WE'RE AN INSTRUMENT
OF CIVILIZATION.
AND IT'S A BETTER
OPPORTUNITY
FOR A SCIENTIST
TO STUDY THE UNIVERSE
THAN HE COULD AT THE
VULCAN SCIENCE ACADEMY.
PERHAPS.
BUT SAREK WANTED SPOCK
TO FOLLOW HIS TEACHINGS
AS SAREK FOLLOWED
THE TEACHINGS OF HIS
OWN FATHER.
THEY ARE BOTH...STUBBORN.
A HUMAN TRAIT, CAPTAIN?
[COMMUNICATOR SIGNAL]
[UHURA]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
EXCUSE ME.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, I'VE PICKED UP
SOME SORT OF SIGNAL.
JUST A FEW SYMBOLS.
NOTHING INTELLIGIBLE.
SOURCE?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
BOTHERS ME, SIR.
IMPOSSIBLE TO LOCATE.
THERE WASN'T
ENOUGH OF IT.
SENSORS SHOW NOTHING
IN THE AREA,
BUT IT WAS A STRONG SIGNAL,
AS THOUGH IT WAS VERY CLOSE.
GO TO ALERT STATUS 4.
BEGIN LONG-RANGE
SCANNING. KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3842.4.
THE INTERPLANETARY
CONFERENCE
WILL CONSIDER THE PETITION
OF THE CORIDAN PLANETS
TO BE ADMITTED
TO THE FEDERATION.
THE CORIDAN SYSTEM
HAS BEEN CLAIMED
BY SOME OF THE RACES
NOW ABOARD OUR SHIP
AS DELEGATES--
RACES WHO HAVE
STRONG PERSONAL REASONS
FOR KEEPING CORIDAN
OUT OF THE FEDERATION.
THE MOST PRESSING PROBLEM
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE
IS TO MAKE SURE
OPEN WARFARE
DOES NOT BREAK OUT
AMONG THE DELEGATES
BEFORE
THE CONFERENCE BEGINS.
MR. AMBASSADOR,
I UNDERSTAND
YOU HAD RETIRED
BEFORE THIS CONFERENCE
WAS CALLED.
FORGIVE MY CURIOSITY,
BUT AS A DOCTOR,
I'M INTERESTED
IN VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY.
ISN'T IT UNUSUAL
FOR A VULCAN TO RETIRE
AT YOUR AGE?
AFTER ALL,
YOU'RE ONLY 102.
102.437 PRECISELY,
DOCTOR,
MEASURED IN YOUR YEARS.
I HAD OTHER CONCERNS.
AMBASSADOR.
SAREK OF VULCAN.
DO YOU VOTE
TO ADMIT CORIDAN
TO THE FEDERATION?
THE VOTE WILL NOT
BE TAKEN HERE,
AMBASSADOR GAV.
MY GOVERNMENT'S
INSTRUCTIONS WILL BE HEARD
IN THE COUNCIL
CHAMBERS ON BABEL.
NO!
YOU!
HOW DO YOU VOTE,
SAREK OF VULCAN?
WHY MUST YOU KNOW,
TELLARITE?
IN COUNCIL,
HIS VOTE CARRIES OTHERS.
I WILL KNOW
WHERE HE STANDS...
AND WHY.
TELLARITES DO NOT
ARGUE FOR REASONS.
THEY SIMPLY ARGUE.
NO. YOU--
GENTLEMEN.
AMBASSADOR SAREK
IS QUITE CORRECT
WHEN HE POINTS OUT
THIS IS NOT THE COUNCIL
CHAMBER OF BABEL.
I AM FULLY AWARE
THAT THE ADMISSION
OF CORIDAN
IS A HIGHLY DEBATABLE
ISSUE,
BUT YOU WON'T
SOLVE IT HERE.
YOU ARE CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
QUITE LOGICAL.
MY APOLOGIES,
CAPTAIN.
YOU WILL EXCUSE ME.
HAVE YOU MET GAV
BEFORE, AMBASSADOR?
WE DEBATED
DURING MY LAST
COUNCIL SESSION.
AMBASSADOR.
AMBASSADOR GAV LOST.
SPOCK, I'VE ALWAYS
SUSPECTED
THAT YOU WERE
A LITTLE MORE HUMAN
THAN YOU LET ON.
MRS. SAREK,
I KNOW ABOUT THE
RIGOROUS TRAINING
OF THE VULCAN YOUTH,
BUT TELL ME,
DID HE EVER
RUN AND PLAY
LIKE THE HUMAN
CHILDREN, EVEN
IN SECRET?
WELL, HE, UH...
HE DID HAVE
A PET SEHLAT
HE WAS VERY FOND OF.
SEHLAT?
IT'S SORT OF A--
A FAT TEDDY BEAR.
A TEDDY BEAR?
EXCUSE ME, DOCTOR.
IT HAS BEEN
A RATHER LONG DAY
FOR MY WIFE.
CAPTAIN.
AMBASSADOR.
A TEDDY BEAR.
NOT PRECISELY, DOCTOR.
ON VULCAN,
THE TEDDY BEARS
ARE ALIVE,
AND THEY HAVE
6-INCH FANGS.
[COMMUNICATOR SIGNAL]
[CHEKOV]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, SENSORS
ARE REGISTERING
AN UNIDENTIFIED
VESSEL PACING US.
ON MY WAY.
ALL DUTY PERSONNEL
ON YELLOW ALERT.
DON'T ALARM THE PASSENGERS.
KIRK OUT.
REPORT.
A SMALL SHIP, CAPTAIN.
IT'S BEEN THERE
FIVE MINUTES, REMAINING
OUTSIDE PHASER RANGE,
AT EXTREME LIMIT
OF SENSORS.
IDENTIFICATION,
SPOCK?
SENSORS INDICATE
THE SIZE OF A SCOUT SHIP,
BUT THE CONFIGURATION
IS UNFAMILIAR.
MOST UNUSUAL.
DOES SHE ANSWER A HAIL?
I'VE TRIED
ALL FREQUENCIES
AND HOOKED IN
THE UNIVERSAL
TRANSLATOR.
NO RESPONSE, SIR.
MAINTAIN TRANSLATOR
BROADCAST.
CHECK RECORDS
FOR AUTHORIZED SHIPS.
STARFLEET RECORDS
NO AUTHORIZED VESSEL
IN THIS QUADRANT
EXCEPT OURS.
CARE TO GUESS
WHAT SHE IS?
GUESS, CAPTAIN?
I SHALL NEED MORE DATA
FOR MY ESTIMATE.
MR. CHEKOV, PLOT COURSE
TO INTERCEPT THAT VESSEL.
I WANT TO SEE
WHAT SHE LOOKS LIKE CLOSE UP.
AYE, SIR.
YOU EMBARRASSED SPOCK
THIS EVENING.
NOT EVEN A MOTHER
MAY DO THAT.
HE IS A VULCAN.
HE'S ALSO HUMAN.
HE'S A STARFLEET OFFICER.
I THOUGHT
YOU DIDN'T APPROVE
OF STARFLEET.
IT IS NOT A QUESTION
OF APPROVAL.
THE FACT EXISTS--
HE IS IN STARFLEET.
HE MUST COMMAND RESPECT
IF HE IS TO FUNCTION.
SAREK, YOU'RE
PROUD OF HIM,
AREN'T YOU?
YOU'RE SHOWING
ALMOST HUMAN PRIDE
IN YOUR SON.
IT DOES NOT
REQUIRE PRIDE
TO ASK THAT SPOCK
BE GIVEN THE RESPECT
WHICH IS HIS DUE,
NOT AS MY SON,
BUT AS SPOCK.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
NOT REALLY,
BUT IT DOESN'T MATTER.
I LOVE YOU ANYWAY.
I KNOW.
IT ISN'T LOGICAL.
VESSEL CHANGING COURSE,
HEADING TOWARD US
AT HIGH WARP SPEED.
READY MAIN PHASERS.
PHASERS ARMED
AND READY, SIR.
INTERESTING.
THEY WERE TRAVELING
AT APPROXIMATELY WARP 10.
BACK ON ORIGINAL COURSE,
MR. CHEKOV.
REPORT ON
INTRUDER'S MOVEMENTS.
CAPTAIN, STARFLEET
ACKNOWLEDGES REPORT
ON OUR SITUATION
AND CONFIRMS--
NO AUTHORIZED
FEDERATION VESSEL
IN THIS QUADRANT.
BACK ON ORIGINAL
HEADING, CAPTAIN.
THE INTRUDER CHANGED COURSE
IMMEDIATELY AFTER WE DID.
IT'S...PARALLELING US
AGAIN.
WELL, WE HAVE A SHADOW.
FASTER, MORE MANEUVERABLE...
AND UNIDENTIFIED.
MR. SPOCK, FULL ANALYSIS
OF SENSOR READINGS.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHO THAT INTRUDER IS.
VULCAN,
I WOULD SPEAK TO YOU.
IT DOES SEEM UNAVOIDABLE.
HOW DO YOU VOTE
ON THE CORIDAN
ADMISSION?
YOU SEEM UNWILLING
TO WAIT
FOR THE COUNCIL MEETING,
AMBASSADOR.
NO MATTER.
WE FAVOR ADMISSION.
YOU FAVOR? WHY?
UNDER FEDERATION LAW,
CORIDAN CAN BE PROTECTED
AND ITS WEALTH ADMINISTERED
FOR THE BENEFIT
OF ITS PEOPLE.
THAT'S WELL FOR YOU.
VULCAN HAS NO MINING
INTEREST.
CORIDAN HAS
NEARLY UNLIMITED WEALTH
OF DILITHIUM CRYSTALS,
BUT IT IS UNDERPOPULATED
AND UNPROTECTED.
THIS INVITES ILLEGAL
MINING OPERATIONS.
ILLEGAL?
YOU ACCUSE US?
SOME OF YOUR SHIPS
HAVE BEEN CARRYING
CORIDAN DILITHIUM CRYSTALS.
YOU CALL US THIEVES?
GENTLEMEN.
WHATEVER ARGUMENTS YOU HAVE
BETWEEN YOURSELVES
IS YOUR BUSINESS.
MY BUSINESS
IS RUNNING THE SHIP.
AND AS LONG AS I COMMAND,
THERE WILL BE ORDER.
OF COURSE, CAPTAIN.
UNDERSTOOD.
THERE WILL BE PAYMENT
FOR YOUR SLANDER,
SAREK.
THREATS ARE ILLOGICAL.
AND PAYMENT
IS USUALLY EXPENSIVE.
SECURITY TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
LIEUTENANT JOSEPH,
SIR.
I'M ON DECK 11,
SECTION A-3.
I'VE JUST FOUND
ONE OF THE TELLARITES
MURDERED.
I THINK IT'S THE
AMBASSADOR HIMSELF, SIR.
HOW WAS HE KILLED?
HIS NECK WAS BROKEN.
BY AN EXPERT.
EXPLAIN.
WELL, FROM THE NATURE
AND LOCATION OF THE
BREAK, I'D SAY
THE KILLER KNEW
EXACTLY WHERE
TO APPLY PRESSURE
TO SNAP THE NECK
INSTANTLY.
WHO ABOARD WOULD
HAVE THAT KNOWLEDGE?
VULCANS.
ON VULCAN,
THE METHOD IS CALLED
TAL-SHAYA.
IT WAS CONSIDERED
A MERCIFUL FORM
OF EXECUTION
IN ANCIENT TIMES.
SPOCK...
A SHORT TIME AGO,
I BROKE UP AN
ARGUMENT BETWEEN
GAV AND YOUR FATHER.
INDEED, CAPTAIN?
INTERESTING.
INTERESTING?
SPOCK, DO YOU REALIZE
THAT MAKES YOUR FATHER
THE MOST LIKELY SUSPECT?
VULCANS DO NOT
APPROVE OF VIOLENCE.
ARE SAYING HE
COULDN'T HAVE DONE IT?
NO, CAPTAIN.
I'M MERELY SAYING
IT WOULD BE
ILLOGICAL TO
KILL WITHOUT REASON.
BUT IF HE HAD
A REASON...
COULD HE HAVE DONE IT?
IF THERE WERE A REASON,
MY FATHER IS QUITE CAPABLE
OF KILLING...
LOGICALLY AND EFFICIENTLY.
MRS. SAREK, I'M
SORRY TO DISTURB YOU.
I MUST SPEAK
TO YOUR HUSBAND.
WELL, HE'S BEEN
GONE FOR SOME TIME.
IT'S HIS HABIT
TO MEDITATE IN PRIVATE
BEFORE RETIRING.
WHAT'S WRONG? SPOCK?
YOU WANT SOMETHING
OF ME, CAPTAIN?
AMBASSADOR,
THE TELLARITE GAV
HAS BEEN MURDERED.
HIS NECK
WAS BROKEN,
MR. AMBASSADOR,
BY WHAT
SPOCK DESCRIBES
AS TAL-SHAYA.
INDEED.
INTERESTING.
YES.
AMBASSADOR...
WHERE WERE YOU
DURING THE PAST
HOUR?
CAPTAIN, YOU'RE NOT
ACCUSING HIM?
MOTHER.
IF ONLY ON
CIRCUMSTANTIAL EVIDENCE,
HE IS A LOGICAL SUSPECT.
I QUITE AGREE.
THEN WHERE WERE YOU
DURING THE HOUR?
IN PRIVATE MEDITATION,
CAPTAIN.
SPOCK WILL TELL YOU
THAT SUCH MEDITATION IS
A PERSONAL EXPERIENCE,
NOT TO BE DISCUSSED.
ESPECIALLY NOT
WITH EARTHMEN.
WELL, THAT'S A VERY
CONVENIENT EXCUSE,
AMBASSADOR.
[GASPS]
SAREK.
WHAT'S WRONG?
IT'S DIFFICULT TO SAY
WITH VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY,
BUT I BELIEVE
IT'S SOMETHING TO DO WITH
HIS CARDIOVASCULAR SYSTEM.
CAN YOU HELP HIM?
I DON'T KNOW
THAT YET, EITHER.
[SENSOR BEEPS]
SPOCK.
YES, CAPTAIN.
I GET SENSOR READINGS
OF TRI-TRITANIUM
FROM THE ALIEN SHIP'S HULL.
I'M SORRY
ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
YES, IT COULD
ADVERSELY AFFECT
OUR MISSION.
AREN'T YOU
WORRIED ABOUT HIM?
WORRY IS A HUMAN
EMOTION, CAPTAIN.
I ACCEPT
WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
THE SHIP'S HULL
SEEMS TO HAVE
A HIGH DENSITY LEVEL
OR IS CLOAKED AGAINST
SENSOR PROBES.
IT IS MANNED,
BUT SENSORS CANNOT
MAKE OUT SPECIFICS.
I SEE.
WELL, THE ROMULANS
HAVE NOTHING LIKE IT.
CERTAINLY NOT
THE FEDERATION
OR THE NEUTRAL PLANETS.
WHAT ABOUT THE KLINGONS?
I THINK IT UNLIKELY
IT IS ONE OF THEIRS.
WHO, THEN?
CAPTAIN?
I'VE PICKED UP THE LAST PART
OF A TRANSMISSION,
JUST LIKE THAT OTHER ONE.
I PUT THE RECORDER
AND THE DIRECTIONAL LOCATOR
ON IT IMMEDIATELY.
MR. CHEKOV,
DIRECTIONAL LOCATOR
INDICATES SOURCE
BEARING 27 MARK 8.
IT'S THE INTRUDER SHIP, SIR.
SWITCH RECORDER
TO MR. SPOCK'S STATION
FOR DECODE, LIEUTENANT.
SIR.
THE DIRECTIONAL LOCATOR
INDICATES...
RECEPTION POINT SOMEWHERE
WITHIN THE BODY
OF THIS SHIP.
A PERSONAL RECEIVER?
SOMEBODY ON BOARD
IS IN CONTACT
WITH THAT VESSEL?
POSSIBLY, CAPTAIN.
BUT I CANNOT DECODE
THIS TRANSMISSION.
WHY NOT?
IT IS IN NO KNOWN CODE.
THERE'S NO
DETECTABLE PATTERN.
NO STANDARD REFERENCES
APPLY.
ARE ANY CONCLUSIONS
POSSIBLE FROM
THE INFORMATION?
ONLY NEGATIVE.
IT FITS NONE
OF OUR COMPUTER RECORDS,
AND IT IS ALIEN.
MURDER?
SOMEONE OUT THERE
PLAYING TAG?
LIEUTENANT, YOU'VE GOT
YOUR SENSOR LOCATOR
ON A WIDE BEAM.
WE'VE ESTABLISHED A
RECEIVER ONBOARD THIS
VESSEL.
TIGHTEN YOUR FIELD
TO THE INTERIOR
OF THE SHIP.
YES, SIR.
IF THAT ALIEN VESSEL
STARTS TRANSMITTING AGAIN,
I WANT TO KNOW
WHO ON BOARD
THE ENTERPRISE
IS RECEIVING.
BONES, HOW IS HE?
WELL, AS FAR AS I CAN
TELL FROM INSTRUMENT
READINGS,
OUR PRIME SUSPECT HAS A
MALFUNCTION IN ONE OF
THE HEART VALVES.
IT'S SIMILAR
TO A HEART ATTACK
IN A HUMAN.
BUT WITH
VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO TELL
WITHOUT AN OPERATION.
MRS. SAREK,
HAS HE HAD
ANY PREVIOUS ATTACKS?
NO.
YES.
THERE WERE THREE OTHERS.
MY PHYSICIAN PRESCRIBED
BENJISIDRINE FOR
THE CONDITION.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL ME?
THERE WAS NOTHING
YOU COULD HAVE DONE.
AMBASSADOR...
WHEN DID YOU HAVE
THESE ATTACKS?
TWO BEFORE
WE LEFT VULCAN.
THE THIRD,
A FEW HOURS AGO.
I WAS ON THE
OBSERVATION DECK.
WHEN THE TELLARITE
WAS MURDERED,
I WAS QUITE INCAPACITATED.
THERE WERE
NO WITNESSES?
NONE.
DOCTOR,
DO YOU PROPOSE SURGERY
FOR THE HEART DEFECT?
I'M NOT SURE.
IT'S TOUGH ENOUGH
ON A HUMAN.
ON A VULCAN,
AN ORDINARY OPERATION'S
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
WHY?
BECAUSE OF THE CONSTRUCTION
OF THE VULCAN HEART.
I SUGGEST THAT
A CRYOGENIC OPEN-HEART
PROCEDURE
WOULD BE
THE LOGICAL APPROACH.
YES, UNQUESTIONABLY.
BONES,
WHAT ABOUT IT?
WELL, I'M GLAD SOMEBODY'S
ASKING ME SOMETHING
AROUND HERE.
WELL, THE PROCEDURE
THEY'RE DISCUSSING
WOULD REQUIRE
TREMENDOUS AMOUNTS
OF BLOOD FOR THE PATIENT.
DOCTOR.
YES.
I'VE CHECKED
THE BLOOD BANK.
THERE ISN'T ENOUGH
VULCAN BLOOD AND
PLASMA ONBOARD
TO EVEN BEGIN AN
OPERATION OF
THIS TYPE.
THERE ARE
OTHER VULCANS
ABOARD.
MY BLOOD TYPE
IS T-NEGATIVE.
SOMEWHAT RARE,
EVEN FOR A VULCAN.
YES, I'D SAY THAT'S RARE.
MY BLOOD IS T-NEGATIVE, DOCTOR.
WE'VE RUN A NUMBER
OF BLOOD TESTS
ON MR. SPOCK.
IT ISN'T TRUE VULCAN
BLOOD, EITHER.
IT HAS HUMAN BLOOD
ELEMENTS IN IT.
IT SHOULD BE POSSIBLE
TO FILTER OUT THE
HUMAN FACTORS.
EVEN YOU COULDN'T GIVE
THAT MUCH BLOOD, SPOCK.
IT WOULD KILL YOU.
BONES.
MRS. SAREK,
YOU MUST UNDERSTAND
THE CHANCES
ARE EXTREMELY SMALL
TO FIND A WAY
TO PRODUCE SUFFICIENT
T-NEGATIVE BLOOD.
INDEED.
I WOULD ESTIMATE
THE ODDS--
PLEASE DON'T.
DOCTOR.
I SEE IT, SPOCK,
BUT THAT
WAS A RIGELIAN.
RIGELIAN PHYSIOLOGY
IS VERY SIMILAR
TO VULCAN.
"SIMILAR" IS NOT
GOOD ENOUGH.
IT'S STILL EXPERIMENTAL.
BUT IT DOES
LOOK PROMISING.
SPOCK, WE WOULD NEED SUCH
GREAT AMOUNTS OF BLOOD
THAT, EVEN IF THE DRUG
WORKED ON THE VULCANS,
AS WELL AS A RIGELIAN,
WHICH I'M DOUBTFUL,
IT WOULD STILL DRAIN
SAREK TO A CRITICAL LEVEL.
I CONSIDER THE
SAFETY FACTOR LOW,
BUT ACCEPTABLE.
PLUS THE FACT
I'VE NEVER OPERATED
ON A VULCAN BEFORE.
OH, I'VE STUDIED
THE ANATOMICAL TYPES.
I KNOW WHERE
ALL THE ORGANS ARE.
BUT THAT'S
A LOT DIFFERENT
FROM ACTUAL
SURGICAL EXPERIENCE.
SO IF I DON'T KILL HIM
WITH THE OPERATION,
THE DRUG PROBABLY WILL.
WHAT DRUG, DOCTOR?
MY HUSBAND IS ASLEEP.
WHAT DRUG?
A CHEMICAL STIMULANT
TO SPEED UP REPRODUCTION
AND REPLACEMENT OF BLOOD
IN THE BODY.
IT'S
ONLY EXPERIMENTAL.
IT HAS BEEN
USED SUCCESSFULLY
ON TEST SUBJECTS
ON RIGEL 5.
IT PLACES
A TREMENDOUS STRAIN
ON THE SPLEEN
AND THE LIVER.
IN SAREK'S
CONDITION,
THE STIMULANT
WOULD KILL HIM.
NURSE CHAPEL,
I UNDERWENT A PHYSICAL
EXAMINATION LAST WEEK.
WOULD YOU PULL
THOSE RECORDS, PLEASE?
ALREADY PULLED.
YOU'RE PERFECTLY
HEALTHY, MR. SPOCK.
WHAT HAS THAT GOT--
YOU'RE GOING
TO USE IT ON YOURSELF--
A TRANSFUSION FROM
YOU TO YOUR FATHER?
IT WOULD SEEM
THE ONLY ANSWER.
IT COULD DAMAGE
YOU INTERNALLY.
IT COULD KILL YOU.
I'M SORRY, SPOCK.
I CAN'T SANCTION IT.
AND I REFUSE
TO PERMIT IT.
I WON'T RISK
BOTH OF YOU.
THEN YOU AUTOMATICALLY
CONDEMN SAREK TO DEATH.
AND YOU, DOCTOR,
HAVE NO LOGICAL
ALTERNATIVE, EITHER.
IF YOU DO NOT OPERATE,
SAREK WILL DIE.
YOU NOW HAVE THE MEANS
TO PERFORM THE OPERATION.
I AM VOLUNTEERING MYSELF
AS THE BLOOD DONOR.
I'LL BE AT MY STATION
UNTIL YOU REQUIRE ME.
UHH!
AGH! OHH!
UNGH!
BRIDGE.
SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
I'M ON DECK FIVE
NEAR MY QUARTERS.
I'VE BEEN ATTACKED
BY AN ANDORIAN.
SECURITY...
SE-SECURITY TEAM.
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN?
[MR. SPOCK]
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3843.4.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
IN TEMPORARY COMMAND.
THE CAPTAIN HAS BEEN
CRITICALLY WOUNDED
BY ONE OF THE DELEGATES
TO THE BABEL CONFERENCE.
THE SHIP
IS ON ALERT STATUS.
WE ARE STILL BEING FOLLOWED
BY THE INTRUDER VESSEL.
IT'S A BAD WOUND--
PUNCTURED LEFT LUNG.
A CENTIMETER
OR SO LOWER,
IT'D HAVE GONE
THROUGH THE HEART.
I'LL BE IN THE BRIG
QUESTIONING
THE ANDORIAN PRISONER.
DOCTOR,
THE K-2 FACTOR
IS DROPPING.
SPOCK...
YOUR FATHER
IS MUCH WORSE.
THERE'S NO
LONGER A CHOICE.
I HAVE TO OPERATE
IMMEDIATELY.
WE CAN BEGIN AS SOON
AS YOU'RE PREPARED.
NO, DOCTOR.
WHAT?
MY FIRST RESPONSIBILITY
IS TO THE SHIP.
OUR PASSENGERS' SAFETY
IS BY STARFLEET ORDER
OF FIRST IMPORTANCE.
WE ARE BEING FOLLOWED
BY AN ALIEN,
POSSIBLY HOSTILE VESSEL.
I CANNOT
RELINQUISH COMMAND
UNDER THESE CIRCUMSTANCES.
YOU CAN TURN COMMAND
OVER TO SCOTTY.
ON WHAT GROUNDS,
DOCTOR?
COMMAND REQUIREMENTS
DO NOT RECOGNIZE
PERSONAL PRIVILEGE.
I'LL BE IN THE BRIG
INTERROGATING
THE ANDORIAN.
HE IS THELEV,
A MINOR MEMBER
OF MY STAFF.
I KNOW
NOTHING OF HIM
EXCEPT THAT HE HAS
SERVED ADEQUATELY.
HE HAS BEEN SUBJECTED
TO QUESTIONING
UNDER VERIFIER SCAN
AND TRUTH DRUG.
HE REVEALS NOTHING.
I SUGGEST HIS MIND
HAS BEEN SO CONDITIONED
AS PART OF A
PRECONCEIVED PLAN.
MY PEOPLE
ARE A VIOLENT RACE,
BUT WE'VE NO QUARREL
WITH CAPTAIN KIRK.
APPARENTLY THELEV DID.
YOU SUGGEST A PLOT.
HOW COULD
IT PROFIT US
TO HARM THE CAPTAIN?
I DO NOT KNOW.
THERE IS NO LOGIC
IN THELEV'S ATTACK
UPON THE CAPTAIN.
THERE IS NO LOGIC
IN GAV'S MURDER.
PERHAPS YOU
SHOULD FORGET LOGIC
AND DEVOTE YOURSELF
TO MOTIVATIONS
OF PASSION OR GAIN.
THOSE ARE REASONS
FOR MURDER.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
[BUZZ]
COME IN.
SPOCK, YOU MUST
TURN COMMAND OVER
TO SOMEBODY ELSE.
MOTHER, WHEN I
WAS COMMISSIONED,
I TOOK AN OATH
TO CARRY OUT
RESPONSIBILITIES
WHICH WERE CLEARLY
AND EXACTLY SPECIFIED.
ANY COMPETENT OFFICER
CAN COMMAND THIS SHIP.
ONLY YOU CAN
GIVE YOUR FATHER
THE BLOOD TRANSFUSIONS
THAT HE NEEDS TO LIVE.
ANY COMPETENT OFFICER
CAN COMMAND THIS SHIP
UNDER
NORMAL CIRCUMSTANCES.
THE CIRCUMSTANCES
ARE NOT NORMAL.
WE'RE CARRYING
OVER 100 VALUABLE
FEDERATION PASSENGERS.
WE'RE BEING PURSUED
BY AN ALIEN SHIP.
WE ARE SUBJECT
TO POSSIBLE ATTACK.
THERE HAS BEEN MURDER
AND ATTEMPTED MURDER
ON BOARD.
I CANNOT
DISMISS MY DUTIES.
DUTY? YOUR DUTY
IS TO YOUR FATHER.
I KNOW,
BUT THIS MUST
TAKE PRECEDENCE.
IF I COULD
GIVE THE TRANSFUSION
WITHOUT LOSS OF TIME
OR EFFICIENCY,
I WOULD.
SAREK UNDERSTANDS
MY REASON.
WELL, I DON'T.
IT'S NOT HUMAN.
OH, THAT'S NOT
A DIRTY WORD.
YOU'RE HUMAN, TOO.
LET THAT PART OF
YOU COME THROUGH.
YOUR FATHER'S DYING.
MOTHER, HOW CAN
YOU HAVE LIVED
ON VULCAN SO LONG,
MARRIED A VULCAN,
RAISED A SON ON VULCAN,
WITHOUT UNDERSTANDING
WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE A VULCAN?
WELL, IF THIS IS WHAT IT
MEANS, I DON'T WANT TO KNOW.
IT MEANS TO ADOPT
A PHILOSOPHY, A
WAY OF LIFE
WHICH IS LOGICAL
AND BENEFICIAL.
WE CANNOT DISREGARD
THAT PHILOSOPHY
MERELY FOR PERSONAL GAIN,
NO MATTER HOW IMPORTANT
THAT GAIN MIGHT BE.
NOTHING IS AS IMPORTANT
AS YOUR FATHER'S LIFE.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
WHAT MY FATHER WOULD SAY
IF I WERE TO AGREE,
IF I WERE TO GIVE UP
COMMAND OF THIS VESSEL,
JEOPARDIZE
HUNDREDS OF LIVES,
RISK INTERPLANETARY WAR--
ALL FOR THE LIFE
OF ONE PERSON?
WHEN YOU
WERE 5 YEARS OLD
AND CAME HOME
STIFF-LIPPED, ANGUISHED,
BECAUSE THE OTHER
BOYS TORMENTED YOU,
SAYING THAT YOU
WEREN'T REALLY VULCAN...
I WATCHED YOU
KNOWING THAT--
THAT INSIDE...
THAT THE HUMAN PART
OF YOU WAS CRYING...
AND I CRIED, TOO.
THERE MUST BE SOME
PART OF ME IN YOU,
SOME PART THAT I
STILL CAN REACH.
IF BEING VULCAN IS
MORE IMPORTANT TO YOU,
THEN YOU'LL STAND THERE
SPEAKING RULES
AND REGULATIONS
FROM STARFLEET
AND VULCAN PHILOSOPHY
AND--AND LET
YOUR FATHER DIE AND...
THEN I'LL HATE YOU
FOR THE REST
OF MY LIFE.
MOTHER...
OH, GO TO HIM, NOW,
PLEASE.
I CANNOT.
[NURSE CHAPEL]
DR. McCOY.
I'D LIKE
TO GET MY HANDS
ON THE GUY
WITH THE SLEDGEHAMMER.
THE ONE WHO HIT YOU?
NO, THE ONE
WHO'S ON MY HEAD.
HOW LONG HAVE I--
OH.
LET THAT BE A LESSON.
JUST LIE THERE
AND BE HAPPY
YOU'RE STILL ALIVE.
HOW'S SAREK?
NOT GOOD.
IF I COULD
ONLY OPERATE.
WHAT'S STOPPING YOU?
I THOUGHT YOU
WERE ALREADY.
I WAS.
WHEN YOU
BECAME INJURED,
SPOCK
ASSUMED COMMAND.
HE'S STAYING THERE
UNTIL YOU GET BACK
ON YOUR FEET,
EVEN IF IT COSTS
SAREK HIS LIFE.
REGULATIONS.
I CAN'T DAMN HIM
FOR HIS LOYALTY,
FOR DOING HIS DUTY,
BUT I'M NOT GOING
TO LET HIM
COMMIT PATRICIDE.
JIM, IF YOU STAND,
YOU COULD START
TO BLEED AGAIN.
BONES,
SAREK WILL DIE
WITHOUT THAT OPERATION,
AND...
YOU CAN'T OPERATE
WITHOUT TRANSFUSIONS
FROM SPOCK.
I'LL CONVINCE SPOCK
I'M ALL RIGHT
AND ORDER HIM
TO REPORT HERE.
AS SOON AS HE
LEAVES THE BRIDGE,
I'LL TURN COMMAND
OVER TO SCOTTY
AND REPORT
TO MY QUARTERS.
WILL THAT FILL
YOUR PRESCRIPTION?
CAPTAIN?
I'LL TAKE OVER,
MR. SPOCK.
YOU REPORT TO SICKBAY
WITH DR. McCOY.
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU
QUITE ALL RIGHT?
I'VE CERTIFIED HIM
PHYSICALLY FIT, MR. SPOCK.
NOW, SINCE I HAVE
AN OPERATION TO PERFORM
AND BOTH OF US
ARE REQUIRED...
GET OUT, SPOCK.
MR. CHEKOV, WHAT'S THE
STATUS OF THE INTRUDER?
UH, NO CHANGE, SIR.
MAINTAINING
ITS DISTANCE.
ANY FURTHER
TRANSMISSIONS,
LIEUTENANT?
NONE, SIR.
CALL MR. SCOTT
TO THE BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN,
THE ALIEN VESSEL
IS MOVING CLOSER.
BELAY THAT ORDER.
I'LL STAY HERE.
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
THE ALIEN SIGNAL AGAIN,
BUT IT'S COMING
FROM INSIDE
THE ENTERPRISE.
SPECIFIC ORIGIN?
FROM THE BRIG, SIR.
SECURITY.
SECURITY, TO THE BRIG.
SEARCH THE PRISONER
IMMEDIATELY.
READINGS, NURSE.
MR. SPOCK'S
BLOOD-REPRODUCTION RATE
IS UP OVER 200%.
SAREK'S HEARTBEAT
HAS RISEN TO 324.
BLOOD PRESSURE--
90 OVER 40, DROPPING.
I WISH I KNEW
WHETHER THAT
WAS GOOD OR BAD.
INITIATE
STERILE FIELD.
MR. SPOCK.
WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
I MUST SEE
THE CAPTAIN.
MY PATIENTS
DON'T WALK OUT
IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN OPERATION.
THE ALIEN SHIP--
I JUST REALIZED THAT
THEIR POWER UTILIZATION
CURVE IS NOT THE NORM.
IT SHOULD BE POSSIBLE...
TO IDENTIFY
THEM THIS WAY.
VERY IMPORTANT.
SO IS YOUR
FATHER'S LIFE.
UHH!
KIRK HERE.
SECURITY HERE.
WE HAD TO STUN
THE ANDORIAN.
HE HAD SOME SORT OF TRANSCEIVER.
IT WAS HIDDEN IN HIS ANTENNA.
CAPTAIN, THE ALIEN SHIP
HAS CHANGED COURSE
AND SPEED--
MOVING DIRECTLY TOWARD
US AT WARP 8.
BRING THE PRISONER
TO THE BRIDGE.
DEFLECTORS ON.
RED ALERT.
PHASERS STAND BY
TO FIRE ON MY ORDER.
AYE, SIR.
SHIELDS UP.
PHASERS MANNED
AND READY, SIR.
CHEKOV, TAKE OVER
SPOCK'S SCANNER.
AYE, SIR.
[EXPLOSION]
TARGET, MR. CHEKOV.
MOVING AWAY.
TURNING NOW.
HE'S COMING AROUND AGAIN.
FIRE AS HE
PASSES, ENSIGN.
A CLEAN MISS, SIR.
REPORT ON HIS
WEAPONRY, MR. CHEKOV.
SENSORS RECORD
STANDARD PHASERS, SIR.
STANDARD PHASERS.
GOOD.
THEY MAY HAVE
MORE SPEED,
BUT THEY'RE
NOT GIANTS.
CAPTAIN, THE
INTERCOMS ARE JAMMED.
ALL THE AMBASSADORS ARE
ASKING WHAT'S GOING ON.
TELL THEM TO TAKE
A GOOD GUESS,
BUT CLEAR THAT
BOARD, LIEUTENANT.
AYE, SIR.
HE'S COMING AROUND AGAIN.
[EXPLOSION]
ONE MORE LIKE THAT,
AND I'M GOING TO
LOSE BOTH THESE MEN.
[EXPLOSION]
FIRE CONTROL LOCKED
INTO COMPUTERS,
CAPTAIN.
ON MY ORDER,
FIRE PHOTON TORPEDOES
2, 4, AND 6.
WIDEST POSSIBLE SCATTER.
AYE, SIR.
FIRE.
FULL SPREAD MISSED, SIR.
THEY'RE MOVING
TOO FAST FOR US.
[EXPLOSIONS]
DOCTOR,
HIS HEART'S STOPPED.
CARDIO-STIMULATE.
[EXPLOSION]
THE SYSTEMS ARE OFF.
THEN GET ME
THAT OLD PORTABLE
CARDIO-STIMULATOR.
AND CALL ENGINEERING
AND HAVE SICKBAY
SYSTEMS PUT ON PRIORITY.
YES, SIR.
NUMBER FOUR SHIELD
HAS BUCKLED, SIR.
AUXILIARY POWER.
SWITCHING OVER.
SHIELDS FIRMING UP.
NUMBER FOUR IS
STILL WEAK, SIR.
IF THEY HIT US THERE
AGAIN, IT'LL GO ALTOGETHER.
[EXPLOSION]
YOUR FRIENDS OUT
THERE ARE GOOD,
BUT THEY'LL HAVE TO
DESTROY THIS SHIP TO WIN.
THAT WAS INTENDED FROM
THE BEGINNING, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE NOT ANDORIAN.
WHO ARE YOU?
[EXPLOSION]
DAMAGE REPORTS COMING
IN, CAPTAIN--
EVERY DECK.
DAMAGE-CONTROL
PROCEDURES, ALL DECKS.
THAT SHIP OUT
THERE HAS PHASERS.
AT LEAST OUR
WEAPONS ARE ALIKE.
NUMBER TWO SHIELD IS GONE, SIR.
ENGINEERING,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
CUT POWER ON PORT SIDE
EXCEPT FOR PHASER BANKS.
AT MY SIGNAL,
CUT STARBOARD POWER.
KIRK OUT.
WHO ARE YOU?
FIND YOUR OWN
ANSWERS, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVEN'T
LONG TO LIVE.
YOU'RE A SPY,
SURGICALLY ALTERED
TO PASS AS AN ANDORIAN,
PLANTED IN THE
AMBASSADOR'S PARTY
TO USE TERROR AND
MURDER TO DISRUPT US
AND PREPARE
FOR THIS ATTACK.
SPECULATION, CAPTAIN.
ENGINEERING,
CUT POWER
ON STARBOARD SIDE.
MAINTAIN
UNTIL FURTHER ORDERS.
CHEKOV.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU SPECULATE.
WE'RE STARTING
TO DRIFT, SIR.
SHALL I HOLD
HER ON COURSE?
NO. STAND BY
YOUR PHASERS,
MR. CHEKOV.
AYE, SIR.
PHASERS
STANDING BY.
HE'S JUST HOVERING
OUT THERE, SIR.
LOOKING US OVER.
WE'RE DEAD
AS FAR AS HE KNOWS.
YOU'RE BAITING HIM.
YOU'RE TRYING
TO LURE HIM IN.
HERE HE COMES.
RANGE DECREASING.
SPEED DROPPING
CLOSE TO SUBLIGHT.
HOLD YOUR FIRE,
MR. CHEKOV.
PHASERS LOCKED
ON TARGET.
RANGE--CLOSING.
75,000 KILOMETERS.
FIRE.
GOT HIM!
SECURE FROM
GENERAL QUARTERS.
LIEUTENANT, OPEN
THE HAILING FREQUENCY.
IF THEY WISH
TO SURRENDER...
THEY COULD NOT
SURRENDER, CAPTAIN.
THEY HAD ORDERS
TO SELF-DESTRUCT.
LIEUTENANT, RELAY
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
TELL THEM
WE HAVE A PRISONER.
AYE, SIR.
ONLY TEMPORARILY, CAPTAIN.
YOU SEE, I HAD ORDERS
TO SELF-DESTRUCT, TOO.
SLOW POISON.
QUITE PAINLESS, ACTUALLY,
BUT THERE'S
NO KNOWN ANTIDOTE.
I ANTICIPATE ANOTHER
10 MINUTES OF LIFE.
TAKE HIM TO SICKBAY.
UHH...
I SEEM TO HAVE...
MISCALCULATED.
SO DID THEY.
MR. CHEKOV,
TAKE OVER.
BONES.
ARE YOU QUITE THROUGH
SHAKING THIS SHIP AROUND?
SPOCK, SAREK--
HOW ARE THEY?
WELL, I DON'T
MIND TELLING YOU,
YOU SURE MAKE IT DIFFICULT
FOR A SURGEON TRYING--
BONES!
CAPTAIN, COME IN.
THAT PIG-HEADED
VULCAN STAMINA--
I COULDN'T HAVE
PULLED THEM THROUGH
WITHOUT IT.
SOME DOCTORS
HAVE ALL THE LUCK.
CAPTAIN, I BELIEVE
YOU'LL FIND THE ALIEN--
WE DAMAGED THEIR SHIP.
THEY DESTROYED THEMSELVES
TO AVOID CAPTURE.
BONES, THELEV'S BODY WILL
BE BROUGHT TO YOUR LAB.
I WANT AN AUTOPSY PERFORMED
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND
HE'S AN ORION, DOCTOR.
ORION?
INTELLIGENCE REPORTS
THAT ORION SMUGGLERS
HAVE BEEN RAIDING
THE CORIDAN SYSTEM.
BUT WHAT WOULD THEY GAIN
BY AN ATTACK ON STARFLEET?
MUTUAL SUSPICION
AND INTERPLANETARY WAR.
YES, OF COURSE, WITH
ORION CAREFULLY NEUTRAL.
THEY'D CLEAN UP
SUPPLYING DILITHIUM
TO BOTH SIDES
AND CONTINUE
TO RAID CORIDAN.
THE THING
THAT CONFUSED ME
WAS THE POWER
UTILIZATION CURVE.
IT MADE THEM SEEM
MORE POWERFUL
THAN A STARSHIP,
OR ANYTHING
KNOWN TO US.
THAT SHIP
WAS CONSTRUCTED
FOR A SUICIDE
MISSION.
SINCE THEY
NEVER INTENDED
TO RETURN
TO THEIR HOME BASE,
THEY COULD
USE 100% POWER
ON THEIR ATTACKS.
THE THING
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS WHY I DIDN'T
THINK OF IT EARLIER.
YOU MIGHT HAVE HAD
SOMETHING ELSE
ON YOUR MIND.
IT HARDLY SEEMS LIKELY.
NO, BUT THANK
YOU, ANYWAY.
AND YOU, SAREK,
WOULD YOU ALSO
SAY THANK YOU
TO YOUR SON?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WELL, FOR SAVING YOUR LIFE.
SPOCK ACTED IN
THE ONLY LOGICAL
MANNER OPEN TO HIM.
ONE DOES NOT
THANK LOGIC, AMANDA.
LOGIC, LOGIC--
I'M SICK TO
DEATH OF LOGIC.
DO YOU WANT TO
KNOW HOW I FEEL
ABOUT YOUR LOGIC?
EMOTIONAL, ISN'T SHE?
SHE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THAT WAY.
INDEED?
WHY DID YOU MARRY HER?
AT THE TIME,
IT SEEMED
THE LOGICAL
THING TO DO.
OH. BONES...
NO, NO.
I'M ALL RIGHT. I'M--
IF YOU KEEP ARGUING
WITH YOUR KINDLY
FAMILY DOCTOR,
YOU'RE GOING TO SPEND
YOUR NEXT 10 DAYS
RIGHT HERE.
IF YOU COOPERATE,
YOU'LL BE OUT IN TWO.
DOCTOR, I THINK
I'LL RETURN TO
MY STATION NOW.
YOU ARE AT YOUR
STATION, MR. SPOCK.
DR. McCOY, I BELIEVE
YOU'RE ENJOYING ALL THIS.
INDEED, CAPTAIN.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
HIM LOOK SO HAPPY.
SHUT UP!
SHH.
SHH!
WELL, WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
I FINALLY
GOT THE LAST WORD.