THEY'RE QUITE LARGE.
7 FEET TALL
IS NOT UNUSUAL.
THEY'RE EXTREMELY
FAST AND STRONG.
LIEUTENANT?
MAKE NO MISTAKE.
THEY CAN BE HIGHLY
DANGEROUS.
THE CAPELLANS' BASIC
WEAPON--THE KLEEAT.
AT ANY DISTANCE
UP TO 100 YARDS,
THEY CAN MAKE IT
ALMOST AS EFFECTIVE
AGAINST A MAN
AS A PHASER.
IN ADDITION TO THIS,
AN ASSORTMENT OF
SWORDS AND KNIVES.
[BOATSWAIN'S CALL]
CALL FROM THE BRIDGE,
CAPTAIN.
Sulu: BRIDGE. HELM, SIR.
YES, MR. SULU.
REPORT.
NOW IN STANDARD ORBIT, SIR.
I'VE PINPOINTED THEIR
ENCAMPMENT BELOW.
VERY GOOD. HAVE THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM STAND BY.
AYE, SIR.
HOW LONG WERE
YOU STATIONED ON
THE PLANET, DOCTOR?
ONLY A FEW MONTHS.
WE FOUND THEM
TOTALLY UNINTERESTED IN
MEDICAL AID OR HOSPITALS.
THEY BELIEVE THAT ONLY
THE STRONG SHOULD SURVIVE.
ANALYSIS, GENTLEMEN.
ORDINARILY,
UNDER THESE CIRCUMSTANCES,
I WOULD RECOMMEND
A LARGE, WELL-ARMED
LANDING PARTY.
YES, BUT IN THIS CASE,
WITH THE MORE
PEOPLE WE TAKE DOWN,
THE GREATER CHANCE
WE HAVE OF VIOLATING
ONE OF THEIR TABOOS.
AGREED.
ONCE THEY'VE GOT IT
INTO THEIR HEADS
WE'RE SHOWING FORCE,
YOU CAN FORGET THEM
SIGNING ANY MINING TREATY.
VERY WELL.
SCOTTY,
YOU'RE IN COMMAND.
BEAR IN MIND THAT
THE KLINGONS HAVE BEEN
SIGHTED IN THIS SECTOR.
WHILE WE'RE NEGOTIATING
DOWN THERE,
WE DON'T WANT THE
ENTERPRISE TO BECOME
AN INCIDENT UP HERE.
Scotty: AYE, SIR.
WE'LL KEEP ON OUR TOES.
Man: HALT!
YOU ARE OF
THE EARTH VESSEL?
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
WE COME WITH
OPEN HEARTS
AND HANDS.
A KLINGON!
GRANT, NO!
DON'T MOVE A MUSCLE.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3497.2.
PLANET CAPELLA IV.
THE RARE MINERAL TOPELINE,
VITAL TO
THE LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS
OF PLANETOID COLONIES
HAS BEEN DISCOVERED
IN ABUNDANCE HERE.
OUR MISSION--
OBTAIN A MINING AGREEMENT.
BUT WE HAVE DISCOVERED
A KLINGON AGENT HAS PRECEDED US
TO THE PLANET,
A DISCOVERY WHICH HAS
COST THE LIFE
OF ONE OF MY CREWMEN.
I AM UNAWARE OF ANY
STATE OF WAR
BETWEEN
OUR PEOPLES, CAPTAIN.
JIM!
OR IS IT YOUR POLICY TO
KILL KLINGONS ON SIGHT?
HE WAS YOUNG...
AND INEXPERIENCED!
DOES MAAB KNOW
THAT THE KLINGONS
ARE OUR SWORN ENEMIES,
BY THEIR OWN WORDS?
WE UNDERSTAND ONLY THAT
HE ALSO OFFERS THINGS
OF VALUE FOR OUR ROCKS,
THAT HE HAS FREELY
HANDED US HIS WEAPONS
AND OTHER DEVICES.
WILL YOU DO THE SAME?
LET ME CALL MY SHIP
AND INFORM THEM--
TO BRING DOWN AN ATTACK
UPON THEIR VILLAGE?
IT IS AS I TOLD YOU,
MAAB.
EARTH MEN FEAR
TO BARGAIN HONESTLY.
WILL YOU HAND US
YOUR WEAPONS?
SO THEY KEEP THEIR WORD...
SCRUPULOUSLY.
THEY'RE UNUSUALLY HONEST.
IS THAT WHAT I HEARD
YOU SAY IN THE
BRIEFING ROOM, DOCTOR?
YES, I MENTIONED THAT.
HE ALSO MENTIONED
THAT THEY CAN BE
HIGHLY DANGEROUS.
DANGEROUS IF LIED TO,
IF THEIR CUSTOMS
ARE VIOLATED.
BUT WE LIED TO NO ONE,
DOCTOR.
WE VIOLATED NO CUSTOMS.
PERHAPS YOU'LL EXPLAIN TO ME
WHY ONE OF MY MEN IS DEAD.
BECAUSE HE WAS DRAWING
A WEAPON ON ANOTHER
OF THEIR GUESTS.
GRANT LOOKED UP,
SAW A KLINGON,
MADE A PURELY INSTINCTIVE
DEFENSIVE MOVE.
AND WHAT'S A KLINGON
DOING DOWN HERE
AMONG YOUR SCRUPULOUSLY
HONEST FRIENDS ANYWAY?
LOOK, JIM, I KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS TO YOU
TO LOSE A CREWMAN.
THAT'S ONLY ONE DOWN,
DOCTOR.
THERE'S OVER 400 MORE
UP THERE IN ORBIT.
AND IF THERE'S
A KLINGON DOWN HERE,
THERE MIGHT BE
A KLINGON SHIP
UP THERE SOMEWHERE.
MR. SCOTT.
I'M PICKING UP SOMETHING
ON THE SENSORS, SIR.
SEEMS TO BE ANOTHER SHIP.
WELL, LET'S PUT IT
ON THE SCREEN.
IT'S JUST AT THE EDGE
OF OUR SENSOR RANGE, SIR.
HARD TO GET
AN EXACT READING.
YOU THINK
IT'S A KLINGON SHIP?
WHO ELSE WOULD BE
PLAYING CAT AND MOUSE
WITH A STARSHIP?
WELL...IT CAN'T HURT
US MUCH OUT THERE
BOBBING ABOUT
LIKE THAT.
NO NEED TO CALL
THE CAPTAIN YET.
BONES...
YES, CAPTAIN?
I SHOULDN'T HAVE
CHEWED YOU OUT.
I'M SORRY.
I UNDERSTAND.
Spock: INEFFICIENT, HOWEVER.
EMOTION, CAPTAIN.
YES, YOU'RE QUITE RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK.
INEFFICIENT...
AND ILLOGICAL.
McCoy: YOU'VE, UH,
SHOWN FRIENDSHIP
BY HANDING OVER
OUR WEAPONS,
AND SHE'S MAKING
A GESTURE IN RETURN.
JIM!
IF YOU TOUCH IT,
HER NEAREST MALE RELATIVE
WILL HAVE TO TRY
TO KILL YOU.
THEY'RE OFFERING YOU
A CHANCE FOR COMBAT.
THEY CONSIDER IT
MORE PLEASURABLE THAN LOVE.
CHURA.
IT WOULD APPEAR,
CAPTAIN,
THAT THEY FIND YOU
A DISAPPOINTMENT.
I AM THE TIER AKAAR.
I LEAD THE 10 TRIBES
OF CAPELLA.
AND THIS IS ELEEN,
A YOUNG WIFE
TO GIVE AN OLD MAN A SON
TO RULE THESE TRIBES.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
FIRST OF ALL, I MUST
PROTEST THE KILLING
OF ONE OF MY CREWMEN.
IF IT WAS YOUR MAN,
WAS IT NOT HIS PRIVILEGE
TO DIE FOR YOU?
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
THEIR CUSTOMS ARE
DIFFERENT, TIER.
AND DIFFERENT FROM
THOSE OF MY PEOPLE,
TOO, TIER.
THE SIGHT OF DEATH
FRIGHTENS THEM.
LET ME TAKE THIS, JIM.
WHAT MAAB HAS SAID
IS TRUE.
OUR CUSTOMS
ARE DIFFERENT.
WHAT THE KLINGON HAS SAID
IS UNIMPORTANT,
AND WE DO NOT
HEAR HIS WORDS.
- HA HA HA!
I JUST CALLED
THE KLINGON A LIAR.
Maab: LAUGHTER, TIER?
IS NOT THE KLINGON
AN HONORED GUEST ALSO?
IT WAS THE EARTH PEOPLE
WHO FIRST BARGAINED
FOR OUR ROCKS.
IS IT NOT BEST
TO HAVE TWO WHO BARGAIN
FOR THE SAME GOODS?
IT IS I WHO SPEAK
FOR THE TRIBE, MAAB.
I SPEAK FOR MANY, TIER.
HEAR THE WORDS
OF THE KLINGON.
WHAT DO EARTH MEN
OFFER YOU?
WHAT HAVE YOU OBTAINED
FROM THEM IN THE PAST?
POWDERS AND LIQUIDS
FOR THE SICK?
HA HA HA.
WE KLINGONS
BELIEVE AS YOU DO.
THE SICK SHOULD DIE.
ONLY THE STRONG
SHOULD LIVE.
EARTH MEN HAVE PROMISED
TO TEACH THE YOUTH
OF YOUR TRIBES
MANY THINGS.
WHAT?
WHAT THINGS?
CLEVERNESS
AGAINST ENEMIES?
THE USE OF WEAPONS?
THE KLINGON SPEAKS
THE TRUTH, AKAAR.
THE EARTH FEDERATION
OFFERS ONE OTHER THING,
AKAAR--
OUR LAWS.
AND THE HIGHEST
OF ALL OUR LAWS STATES
THAT YOUR WORLD
IS YOURS
AND WILL ALWAYS
REMAIN YOURS.
THIS DIFFERS US
FROM THE KLINGONS.
THEIR EMPIRE IS MADE UP
OF CONQUERED WORLDS.
THEY TAKE WHAT THEY WANT
BY ARMS AND FORCE.
GOOD, GOOD.
LET THE KLINGONS
AND THE EARTH MEN
OFFER US AMUSEMENT.
CAPELLANS
WELCOME THIS.
THE EARTH MEN HAVE
DIFFERENT CUSTOMS,
BUT NEVER HAVE THEY
LIED TO OUR PEOPLE.
THERE ARE THOSE OF US
WHO WILL NOT BARGAIN
WITH EARTH MEN, AKAAR.
DO YOU SAY YOU WILL
FIGHT ME, MAAB?
LET THAT BE
YOUR CHOICE, TIER.
WE NEED
OUR COMMUNICATORS,
THOSE DEVICES
ON OUR BELTS.
IF THERE'S
A KLINGON SHIP
SOMEWHERE--
THE SKY
DOES NOT INTEREST ME.
I MUST CONSIDER THE WORDS
I HAVE HEARD.
LEAVE HIM.
THE SHIP'S
DISAPPEARED, SIR.
GONE OUT OF RANGE.
MR. SCOTT,
I'M GETTING A CALL
FROM A VESSEL.
IT'S SO FAINT,
I CAN'T MAKE IT OUT.
PUT A BOOSTER ON IT,
LIEUTENANT.
TRY TO PULL IT IN.
I'VE LOST IT.
IT SOUNDED LIKE
A DISTRESS SIGNAL
FROM AN EARTH VESSEL.
KLINGON!
COMMUNICATORS, WEAPONS.
I HAVE NO QUARREL
WITH YOU, CAPTAIN.
I WISH MERELY TO...
TO RETURN TO MY VESSEL.
TYPE OF VESSEL.
LOCATION.
A SMALL SCOUT SHIP,
CAPTAIN.
WE NEED THE MINERAL, TOO.
I WAS SENT TO NEGOTIATE.
RELEASE HIM.
AKAAR IS DEAD.
I AM THE TIER.
KILL THEM NOW.
WAIT.
IF YOU LEAD
THESE PEOPLE NOW,
BE CERTAIN YOU MAKE
THE RIGHT DECISIONS.
IS THE NEW LEADER
OF THE 10 TRIBES AFRAID?
LET ME KILL HIM
FOR YOU.
OR LET THE KLINGON
AND ME FIGHT.
IT MIGHT AMUSE YOU.
PERHAPS TO BE A TIER
IS TO SEE IN NEW WAYS.
I BEGIN TO LIKE YOU,
EARTH MAN...
AND I SAW FEAR
IN THE KLINGON'S EYE.
WE HAD AN AGREEMENT.
THAT, TOO,
MAY CHANGE, KLINGON.
I HAVE THE SIGNAL CLEAR
NOW, MR. SCOTT.
IT IS A DISTRESS CALL.
IT'S FROM THE S.S. DIERDRE.
THE DIERDRE?
THAT'S A FREIGHTER.
REPORTING
THEY'RE UNDER ATTACK.
THEY'RE RUNNING...
TRYING TO MANEUVER...
IT'S A KLINGON VESSEL
ATTACKING.
HELM?
PICKING IT UP, SIR.
TAKING A FIX.
TRY THE CAPTAIN.
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, CAPTAIN.
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, CAPTAIN.
AAH!
Spock: CAPTAIN, CAREFUL.
YOU CARRY A CHILD
WHO WOULD BE TIER.
I MUST DIE.
NO!
NO MAN MAY TOUCH
THE WIFE OF A TIER.
SHE WAS PREPARED TO DIE,
EARTH MAN.
I WAS PROUD
TO OBEY THE LAWS.
KILL HIM FIRST.
HE LAID HANDS UPON ME.
IT IS MY RIGHT
TO SEE HIM DIE.
ENTERPRISE
TO MR. SPOCK.
DR. McCOY,
COME IN, PLEASE.
I HAVE IT
ON THE SENSORS, SIR.
TIE IN TO MY CHANNEL,
LIEUTENANT.
Uhura: TIED IN.
Man: COMMANDING.
WE ARE UNDER HEAVY ATTACK
BY KLINGON VESSELS.
TWO CONVOY SHIPS
ARE ALREADY DAMAGED.
WE MUST HAVE HELP.
ENTERPRISE, ACKNOWLEDGE.
PLEASE ACKNOWLEDGE.
REPEAT--
INTERCEPTION COURSE
COMPUTED
AND LAID IN, SIR.
PREPARE TO TAKE US
OUT OF ORBIT, MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
SCOTTY...
THE CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE A DISTRESS CALL
FROM A FEDERATION SHIP
UNDER ATTACK.
THAT'S WHERE
OUR DUTY LIES.
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT,
MR. SULU.
AHEAD WARP 5.
Scotty: CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 3498.9,
LIEUTENANT-COMMANDER SCOTT
IN TEMPORARY COMMAND.
WE WERE FORCED
TO LEAVE CAPELLA
TO COME TO THE AID
OF A FEDERATION VESSEL
UNDER ATTACK
BY A KLINGON VESSEL.
WE WERE UNABLE TO CONTACT
OUR LANDING PARTY
BEFORE WE WERE FORCED TO
ANSWER THE DISTRESS SIGNAL.
OUR INABILITY TO REACH
THE LANDING PARTY
IS STRANGE...
AND I AM CONCERNED.
OUR CHECK-IN SIGNAL
IS 1 HOUR, 12 MINUTES
OVERDUE.
SINCE NO RECONNAISSANCE
PARTY HAS APPEARED,
AND SINCE MR. SCOTT
IS NOTABLY EFFICIENT
IN SUCH MATTERS...
I MUST ASSUME
THAT SOMETHING'S
KEEPING THEM BUSY
UP THERE.
THE KLINGON SHIP.
THAT WOULD SEEM
A LOGICAL CONCLUSION.
CAPTAIN, I'M GOING TO
FIX THAT WOMAN'S ARM.
THEY CAN ONLY
KILL ME ONCE
FOR TOUCHING HER.
THAT'S A VERY GOOD IDEA,
BONES.
YES, CAPTAIN,
AN EXCELLENT IDEA.
LET ME SEE
THAT ARM.
YOU WILL NOT
TOUCH ME.
YOU SAY
YOU'RE PREPARED TO DIE.
DOES THAT MEAN
YOU PREFER TO DIE?
I THINK WE CAN GET YOU
SAFELY TO THE SHIP.
YOUR CHOICE? BONES.
TO LIVE...
IS ALWAYS DESIRABLE.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
KLINGON...
THERE'S NOTHING
TO CONCERN YOU THERE.
WE'VE MADE
AN AGREEMENT, MAAB.
I HAVE A RIGHT
TO MY WEAPONS.
WE HAVE THEM
WELL-CARED FOR,
KLINGON.
YOUR WEAPON
WILL BE RETURNED
WHEN OUR BUSINESS
IS COMPLETED.
THAT WAS OUR AGREEMENT.
Man: AFT PHASER CONFIRMING.
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
APPROACHING THE FREIGHTER'S
LAST REPORTED POSITION, SIR.
SENSOR REPORT,
MR. CHEKOV.
NEGATIVE, SIR.
NO DEBRIS,
NO RESIDUAL PARTICLES,
NO TRACES.
MR. SULU,
BEGIN A STANDARD
SEARCH PATTERN.
ALL SCANNERS
FULL INTENSITY,
MR. CHEKOV.
NO SIGNAL AT ALL?
NEGATIVE, SIR.
IT SHOULD BE
ON OUR SCREENS BY NOW.
AT BEST, A FREIGHTER
MIGHT TRAVEL WARP 2.
I'M WELL AWARE
OF A FREIGHTER'S
MAXIMUM SPEED,
MR. SULU.
Kirk, voice-over:
CAPTAIN'S LOG--STARDATE 3499.1.
BEFORE LEAVING
THE CAPELLAN ENCAMPMENT,
WE MANAGED TO RETRIEVE
OUR COMMUNICATORS.
OUR PHASERS
WERE NOT TO BE FOUND.
WE HAVE FLED INTO THE HILLS,
YET WE KNOW THE CAPELLANS
WILL EVENTUALLY FIND US
BY SCENT ALONE,
IF NECESSARY.
AND WE HAVE LEARNED
ONE THING MORE.
THE GIRL ELEEN
HATES THE UNBORN CHILD
SHE IS CARRYING.
STAY WITH HER,
BONES.
NICE PLACE
TO GET TRAPPED IN.
BUT A DEFENSIBLE ENTRANCE,
CAPTAIN.
YES, I SEE.
SCOUT UP THE TRAIL
THAT WAY.
SEE WHAT WE
HAVE IN THE WAY
OF AN EXIT.
I'LL TAKE
A LOOK AROUND.
NOW LISTEN, YOU MAY BE
A CAPELLAN WOMAN
AND THE WIDOW
OF A HIGH TIER,
BUT I'M A DOCTOR,
AND IT'S MY TRADITION TO CARE
FOR THE SICK AND INJURED.
NOW, LET ME SEE
THAT ARM.
[SCANNING]
YOU WILL NOT TOUCH ME
IN THAT MANNER.
NOW YOU LISTEN TO ME,
YOUNG WOMAN.
I'LL TOUCH YOU
IN ANY WAY OR MANNER
THAT MY PROFESSIONAL
JUDGMENT INDICATES.
OHH!
JUST AS I THOUGHT.
IT CAN COME
ANYTIME NOW.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE I'M A DOCTOR,
THAT'S HOW I KNOW.
EVEN THE WOMEN
OF OUR VILLAGE
CANNOT TELL SO MUCH
WITH A TOUCH.
STRANGE HAND.
AND VERY SOFT.
THE WALLS GET HIGHER
AND NARROWER,
BUT THERE IS
A WAY OUT.
GOOD. IF WE COULD
BLOCK OFF THAT ENTRANCE,
HOLD THEM OFF,
IT WOULD GIVE US MORE TIME.
THEY'D HAVE TO GO
AROUND THESE HILLS.
THERE IS ENOUGH
LOOSE ROCK AND SHALE.
DO YOU THINK WE COULD CREATE
A SONIC DISRUPTION
WITH 2 OF
OUR COMMUNICATORS?
ONLY A VERY
SLIGHT CHANCE
IT WOULD WORK.
WELL, IF YOU DON'T THINK
WE CAN, MAYBE WE
SHOULDN'T TRY.
CAPTAIN, I DIDN'T
SAY THAT EXACTLY.
SOUND BEAMS SHOULD PRODUCE
A SYMPATHETIC VIBRATION
ON THE WEAK AREA
OF THAT SLIDE.
[SOUND BEAMS
HUMMING]
[SOUND BEAMS HUMMING]
[RUMBLING]
AAH!
WORRIED ABOUT
THE DELIVERY?
CAPELLANS
AREN'T HUMAN, JIM.
THEY'RE HUMANOID.
THERE ARE CERTAIN
INTERNAL DIFFERENCES.
I DON'T HAVE THE EQUIPMENT
TO HANDLE AN EMERGENCY.
WELL,
IF YOU DON'T THINK
YOU CAN HANDLE IT...
FORGET IT.
I CAN DO IT.
THE LAST THING
I WANT AROUND
IS A HAM-HANDED
SHIP'S CAPTAIN.
NO!
ONLY McCOY.
THERE'S A CAVE
IN THERE.
PROBABLY
THE ONLY SHELTER
AROUND HERE.
I'LL NEED HELP
GETTING HER IN THERE.
NO!
LOOK, I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT AN ESCALATOR!
SPOCK, GIVE ME A HAND!
NO!
I WILL ALLOW
ONLY YOUR TOUCH.
A VESSEL DOESN'T
JUST DISAPPEAR.
THERE'S NOTHING,
MR. SCOTT.
ALL CHANNELS
AND FREQUENCIES
ARE CLEAR.
MR. CHEKOV.
NOTHING, SIR.
IF IT WERE DESTROYED,
I'D PICK UP
DEBRIS READINGS
OF SOME SORT.
IT COULDN'T HAVE RUN
AWAY FROM US, SIR.
NOT A FREIGHTER.
MR. CHEKOV,
PULL THE MICROTAPE
ON THAT DISTRESS CALL.
I WANT IT REPLAYED.
Man: COMMANDING. WE ARE
UNDER HEAVY ATTACK
BY KLINGON VESSELS.
TWO CONVOY SHIPS
ARE ALREADY DAMAGED.
WE MUST HAVE HELP.
ENTERPRISE, ACKNOWLEDGE.
PLEASE ACKNOWLEDGE.
DID YOU HEAR IT?
THEY CALLED US BY NAME.
NOT A GENERAL
DISTRESS SIGNAL,
BUT ONE AIMED
RIGHT AT US.
WOULD THEY NORMALLY CALL
FOR THE NEAREST STARSHIP?
HOW WOULD
A FREIGHTER KNOW
WE WERE ORDERED
INTO THIS SECTOR?
A TRAP.
WE WERE DIVERTED
FROM THE PLANET.
OR IT COULD BE
AN AUTHENTIC
DISTRESS CALL.
WE'LL STAY LONG ENOUGH
TO MAKE CERTAIN.
CONTINUE SEARCH PATTERN.
YES, SIR.
CONTINUING.
BONES, YOU'VE GOT ONE
OF THOSE MAGNASITE
NITRON TABLETS
IN YOUR KIT.
GIVE ME ONE.
JUST A MINUTE.
LET ME GET HER
ON THE ROCK.
THERE YOU GO.
[WHIMPERING]
HERE.
NO, NO.
PAIN IS HERE.
HOW DID YOU ARRANGE
TO TOUCH HER, BONES,
GIVE HER A HAPPY PILL?
NO...
A RIGHT CROSS.
NEVER SEEN THAT
IN A MEDICAL BOOK.
IT'S IN MINE
FROM NOW ON.
NO, NO.
IT'S THERE.
THE--THE PAIN IS THERE.
VEGETATION, CAPTAIN.
EVIDENTLY,
THERE'S WATER NEARBY.
GOOD, BUT WE NEED WEAPONS
JUST AS MUCH AS WE NEED
WATER, SPOCK.
THERE WOULD SEEM TO BE
LITTLE WEAPON POTENTIAL
AT HAND.
FOLLOW ME.
NO!
McCOY...OH!
EASY, EASY. I'M HERE.
NOW...YOU MUST
WANT THE CHILD!
NO!
HERE, CHILD...
BELONGS TO HUSBAND.
SO THEY TAKE
ALL THE CREDIT HERE.
POPPYCOCK!
ANSWER ME.
DO YOU WANT MY HELP?
ALL RIGHT.
SAY TO YOURSELF,
"THE CHILD IS MINE.
IT IS MINE!"
YES...IT'S YOURS.
NO, NO. YOU'VE
GOT IT ALL WRONG.
YES...McCOY...
IT'S YOURS.
NO. SAY TO YOURSELF,
"THE CHILD IS MINE.
IT IS MINE. IT IS--"
UH-OH.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
FORTUNATELY,
THIS BARK HAS SUITABLE
TENSILE COHESION.
YOU MEAN, IT MAKES
A GOOD BOWSTRING.
I BELIEVE I SAID THAT.
[BABY CRYING]
THAT'S MORE LIKE IT.
SINCE THE CAPELLANS
NEVER DEVELOPED THE BOW,
THIS MAY COME
AS BIG A SURPRISE
AS GUNPOWDER WAS
ON EARTH.
[BABY CRYING]
WAH!
NO, NO, MR. SPOCK.
THAT ISN'T THE WAY.
YOU PLACE
THIS ARM UNDER HERE
TO SUPPORT ITS BACK
AND THIS HAND HERE
TO SUPPORT ITS HEAD.
I WOULD RATHER--
I WOULD RATHER NOT.
THANK YOU.
Eleen: McCOY!
BRING OUR CHILD.
OUR CHILD?
I'LL EXPLAIN LATER.
THAT SHOULD PROVE
VERY INTERESTING.
[BABY CRYING]
STILL NEGATIVE,
MR. SCOTT...
ALL SWEEPS.
MR. CHEKOV?
NOTHING.
WE'RE TURNING BACK.
WARP 5, HELM.
WARP 5, SIR.
ON COURSE
FOR CAPELLA IV.
WARP 6 AS SOON AS
SHE'LL TAKE IT,
MR. SULU.
THE CAPTAIN
COULD BE IN TROUBLE
BACK THERE.
MR. SCOTT,
ANOTHER DISTRESS CALL
FROM THE U.S.S. CAROLINA.
IGNORE IT.
MR. SCOTT, THE CAROLINA
IS REGISTERED
IN THIS SECTOR.
IGNORE IT,
LIEUTENANT.
LOG IT AS MY ORDER,
MY RESPONSIBILITY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
SCOTTY, IF IT
SHOULD TURN OUT
TO BE REAL...
THERE'S
AN OLD, OLD SAYING
ON EARTH, MR. SULU.
FOOL ME ONCE,
SHAME ON YOU.
FOOL ME TWICE,
SHAME ON ME.
I KNOW THIS SAYING.
IT WAS INVENTED
IN RUSSIA.
[THUD]
McCoy:
JIM! SPOCK!
WHAT HAPPENED, BONES?
MY PATIENT
SPATTERED ME
WITH A ROCK.
SHE'S GONE.
THE CHILD?
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S IN THERE.
I GUESS I'LL FORGET
PSYCHIATRY,
STICK WITH SURGERY.
I REALLY THOUGHT
SHE'D LEARNED
TO WANT IT.
VIRTUE IS
A RELATIVE TERM, DOCTOR.
SHE'LL HEAD STRAIGHT
TO THE WARRIORS.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
BONES, YOU TOOK
A MEDICAL OATH
LONG BEFORE YOU SIGNED
ABOARD MY SHIP.
THAT SMALL PATIENT
IN THERE NEEDS YOU.
ESTIMATING TO PLANET?
31 MINUTES, SIR.
Man: FOURTH SCANNER
TO BRIDGE--GREEN.
ENGINEERING CONTROL.
Chekov: MR. SCOTT?
SENSORS PICKING UP
A VESSEL AHEAD...
CUTTING ACROSS
OUR PATH.
SUBLIGHT 1/2.
REVERSING
TO SUBLIGHT, 1/2.
IT'S AN ALIEN, SIR.
BY CONFIGURATION...
A KLINGON WARSHIP,
TAKING POSITION...
DIRECTLY IN OUR PATH.
MR. SULU,
SOUND BATTLE STATIONS.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Uhura: THIS IS
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
CALLING UNIDENTIFIED
KLINGON VESSEL. COME IN.
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
CALLING KLINGON VESSEL.
ACKNOWLEDGE, PLEASE.
I HAVE IT ON
THE VIEW SCREEN NOW, SIR.
STILL DISTANT.
HOLDING A POSITION
DEAD AHEAD, SIR.
DRAWING A LINE,
DARING US TO STEP OVER IT.
Sulu: STILL CLOSING.
THE ALIEN'S DIRECTLY
IN OUR LINE OF FLIGHT.
THIS IS THE COMMANDER
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
IDENTIFY YOURSELF
AND YOUR INTENTION.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
CLOSE OUT THE FREQUENCY,
LIEUTENANT.
PHASER BANKS
ARE READY, SIR.
AND WE'LL GO RIGHT DOWN
THEIR THROAT, IF NECESSARY.
LET'S SEE IF THEY HAVE
THE BELLY FOR IT.
BEHIND THE ROCKS
UP THERE.
THE EARTHMEN MAKE
EXCELLENT GAME.
THEIR CLEVERNESS
HAS SURPRISED ME.
THEY MUST DIE.
THAT IS YOUR LAW.
WE WILL HONOR
OUR LAW
AND OUR WORD
TO YOU, KLINGON.
MAAB.
THE CHILD IS DEAD, MAAB.
DO AS YOU WILL WITH ME.
THE EARTHMEN?
DEAD.
I KILLED THEM
AS THEY SLEPT.
IF TRUE...
TAKE US TO THEM.
DO YOU DOUBT
MY WORD, KLINGON?
I'M THE WIFE
OF A TIER.
I WILL DIE
IN MY OWN TENT.
IT IS AN ORDER.
SHE IS THE WIFE
OF A TIER.
NO!
FIRST, WE'LL VERIFY
HER STORY.
IS THIS WHAT
YOUR SWORN WORD
MEANS, KLINGON?
AAH!
Kirk: SPOCK.
SPOCK!
HERE, CAPTAIN.
OVER HERE, CAPTAIN.
SPOCK TO ENTERPRISE.
THE CAVALRY DOESN'T
COME OVER THE HILL IN
THE NICK OF TIME ANYMORE.
IF BY THAT, YOU MEAN
WE CAN'T EXPECT HELP
FROM THE ENTERPRISE,
I MUST AGREE.
DEEM.
THERE'S JUST
ONE THING I WANT.
THE KLINGON?
ONE OF US MUST
GET HIM.
REVENGE, CAPTAIN?
WHY NOT?
THE NEXT MAN
WHO RAISES A WEAPON
DESTROYS ALL OF YOU.
YOU AND YOUR
PRIMITIVE KNIVES
AND YOUR WEAPONS,
I'LL TEACH YOU WHAT
KILLING REALLY MEANS.
KLINGON!
FIGHT!
ARE YOU WARRIORS
OR CHILDREN?
MAAB, I WILL FLEE.
WHEN THE KLINGON
TURNS TO FIRE, I'LL--
AS TIER
OF THE TEN TRIBES,
I GIVE YOU BACK
YOUR LIFE.
MINE IS NOW FORFEIT.
KEEL, STAND READY.
KLINGON!
AAH!
HOLD IT THERE.
DROP YOUR WEAPONS.
WE MISSED YOU,
MR. SCOTT.
WELL, SIR, WE HAD
A WEE BIT OF A RUN-IN
WITH A KLINGON VESSEL,
BUT HE HAD NO STOMACH
FOR FIGHTING.
WE CHECKED THE ENCAMPMENT,
FOUND OUT YOU WERE HERE,
AND HAD NO TROUBLE AT ALL
IN TRACKING YOU DOWN.
I COULD--
[BABY CRIES]
NO. THAT'S NOT
THE WAY TO HANDLE IT.
HERE, LIKE THIS.
HERE, TAKE HIS LITTLE HEAD
LIKE THAT.
THERE,
ARM IN A--THAT'S IT.
SEE HOW EASY?
OOCHY-WOOCHY
KOOTCHIE-KOO.
KOOTCHIE-KOO, CAPTAIN?
AN OBSCURE EARTH
DIALECT, MR. SPOCK.
OOCHY-WOOCHY
KOOTCHIE-KOO.
IF YOU'RE CURIOUS,
CONSULT LINGUISTICS.
WELL, AT ANY RATE, THIS
SHOULD PROVE INTERESTING.
INTERESTING?
WHEN THE WOMAN STARTS
EXPLAINING
HOW THE NEW HIGH TIER
IS ACTUALLY
DR. McCOY'S CHILD.
WHAT'S THAT AGAIN,
MR. SPOCK?
WE DON'T ACTUALLY
UNDERSTAND IT
OURSELVES, MR. SCOTT.
NOR DOES DR. McCOY.
OOCHY-WOOCHY
KOOTCHIE-KOO.
[ELEEN LAUGHING]
CONTACT STARFLEET.
INFORM THEM THE FEDERATION
MINING RIGHTS
ON CAPELLA HAVE BEEN
SECURED BY TREATY,
DOCUMENTS SIGNED
BY THE YOUNG
HIGH CHIEF'S REGENT.
REPORT FOLLOWS.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
THE CHILD'S REGENT?
YES, ELEEN,
A REMARKABLE YOUNG LADY.
REPRESENTING
THE HIGH TIER,
LEONARD JAMES AKAAR.
THE CHILD WAS NAMED
LEONARD JAMES AKAAR?
HAS A KIND OF A RING
TO IT, DON'T YOU
THINK, JAMES?
YES, I THINK IT'S A NAME
DESTINED TO GO DOWN
IN GALACTIC HISTORY,
LEONARD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, SPOCK?
I THINK YOU'RE
BOTH GOING TO BE
INSUFFERABLY PLEASED
WITH YOURSELVES
FOR AT LEAST
A MONTH...SIR.
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT,
MR. SULU.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 1.