WHERE IS EVERYONE?
PERHAPS THEY WEREN'T
EXPECTING US.
OUR ARRIVAL WAS SCHEDULED
WELL IN ADVANCE, DOCTOR.
THE ANNUAL CHECK
OF EVERY SCIENTIFIC
EXPEDITION IS ROUTINE.
I HAD A SUBSPACE CONTACT
WITH A ROBERT JOHNSON,
THE LEADER OF THIS
EXPEDITION, AN HOUR AGO.
DID HE REPORT
ANYTHING WRONG?
NO, YET THERE WAS
SOMETHING WRONG.
I CAN'T QUITE
PIN IT DOWN.
HIS CONVERSATION
WAS DISJOINTED,
HIS THOUGHTS
A LITTLE FOGGY, UNRELATED.
CHEKOV, CHECK THAT BUILDING.
MR. SPOCK AND I
WILL CHECK THIS ONE.
THE REST OF YOU,
TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND ANYONE.
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN! CAPTAIN!
WHAT IS IT?
A MAN, SIR.
IN THERE.
A DEAD MAN.
WELL?
EXACTLY
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE--
DEATH
BY NATURAL CAUSES.
OLD AGE.
QUITE IMPOSSIBLE, DOCTOR.
I RAN A PERSONNEL CHECK
ON THIS ENTIRE EXPEDITION
BEFORE WE BEAMED DOWN.
I ASSURE YOU
THAT NONE OF THEM--
THEY'VE COME TO
PAY THEIR RESPECTS
TO ALVIN.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK OF--
YOU'LL HAVE
TO SPEAK LOUDER.
I SAY I'M CAPTAIN KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M ROBERT JOHNSON.
THIS IS MY WIFE,
ELAINE.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
I'M, UH...
LET ME SEE.
I AM 29,
AND ELAINE IS...
I'M 27.
Captain Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 3478.2.
ON A ROUTINE MISSION
TO RESUPPLY
THE EXPERIMENTAL COLONY
AT GAMMA HYDRA 4,
WE DISCOVERED A MOST
UNUSUAL PHENOMENON.
OF THE SIX MEMBERS
OF THE COLONY,
NONE OF WHOM WERE OVER 30,
WE FOUND FOUR HAD DIED
AND TWO WERE DYING...
OF OLD AGE.
MR. JOHNSON,
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
I CAN HEAR YOU.
NOT DEAF YET,
YOU KNOW.
NOT YET.
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT HAPPENED?
DID YOUR INSTRUMENTS
SHOW ANYTHING?
ELAINE WAS SO BEAUTIFUL.
SO BEAUTIFUL.
HE CAN HEAR YOU, JIM,
BUT HE DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND.
LET'S LET HIM REST.
IF THEY SEEM LUCID,
I'LL BE IN THE BRIEFING ROOM.
STAY SEATED.
LET'S GET STARTED.
I'VE ASKED YOU TO BE
PART OF THIS BRIEFING
BECAUSE GAMMA HYDRA 4
FALLS IN YOUR
ADMINISTRATIVE AREA.
I APPRECIATE THAT, SIR.
DR. WALLACE, AS AN EXPERT
IN ENDOCRINOLOGY,
I'D APPRECIATE YOU WORKING
VERY CLOSELY WITH DR. McCOY.
YES, CAPTAIN.
AND DR. McCOY,
WOULD YOU FILL THEM IN?
THE EXPEDITION IS SUFFERING
FROM EXTREME OLD AGE.
THEY'RE GROWING OLDER
BY THE MINUTE.
MUCH OLDER.
MY EXAMINATIONS
HAVE TURNED UP
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
IN FACT,
I DON'T HAVE A CLUE.
WHAT ABOUT THE ATMOSPHERE
AND ENVIRONMENT, MR. SPOCK?
SENSORS REVEAL NOTHING
WHICH IS INIMICAL
TO HUMAN LIFE.
THE ATMOSPHERE
SCREENS OUT
THE USUAL AMOUNT
OF HARMFUL COSMIC RAYS.
WE'RE CLOSE
TO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
BETWEEN OUR FEDERATION
AND THE ROMULAN EMPIRE.
IT'S POSSIBLE THE ROMULANS
HAVE A NEW WEAPON
AND ARE USING THIS COLONY
AS GUINEA PIGS.
I HAVE ALREADY BEGUN
INVESTIGATION
INTO THAT POSSIBILITY,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD. I WANT YOU ALL TO
CHECK OUT EVERYTHING
IN YOUR OWN DEPARTMENTS.
NO MATTER HOW REMOTE,
HOW FARFETCHED THE NOTION,
I WANT IT RUN DOWN.
WE'LL STAY IN ORBIT
UNTIL WE HAVE THE ANSWER.
I'M SURE YOU
UNDERSTAND
THAT I
AM ANXIOUS TO GET
TO STARBASE 10
TO ASSUME
MY NEW POST.
YES, COMMODORE. WE'LL DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO MAKE SURE
YOU MAKE YOUR DUTY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
DOCTOR, IS THERE
SOMETHING I CAN DO
FOR YOU?
WELL, BE A LITTLE LESS
THE COOL, EFFICIENT CAPTAIN
AND A LITTLE MORE
THE OLD FRIEND.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
SIX YEARS,
FOUR MONTHS,
AND AN ODD NUMBER
OF DAYS.
YOU MEAN
YOU DON'T KNOW?
WELL, IT'S BEEN
A LONG TIME.
THINGS WOULDN'T CHANGE
IF IT STARTED
ALL OVER AGAIN, WOULD IT?
YOU HAVE YOUR JOB,
I HAVE MY SHIP,
AND NEITHER ONE OF US
WILL CHANGE.
YOU SAID IT.
I DIDN'T.
IN ALL THOSE YEARS,
I ONLY HEARD
FROM YOU ONCE--
A STARGRAM WHEN
MY HUSBAND DIED.
YOU KNOW,
YOU NEVER ASKED ME
WHY I GOT MARRIED
AFTER
WE CALLED IT OFF.
WELL, I SUPPOSED THAT
YOU MET SOMEONE YOU LOVED.
I MET A MAN I ADMIRED.
A GREAT MAN.
AND IN THE SAME FIELD.
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO
GIVE UP A THING.
NO.
JUST YOU.
Uhura:  CAPTAIN KIRK,
MR. SPOCK WOULD LIKE
TO SEE YOU ON THE BRIDGE.
I'M ON MY WAY.
STANDARD ORBIT,
CAPTAIN.
MAINTAIN.
I'VE RECHECKED
THE SENSORS, CAPTAIN.
GAMMA HYDRA 4 CHECKS OUT
AS A CLASS "M" PLANET
WITH A CONVENTIONAL
OXYGEN/NITROGEN ATMOSPHERE
AND NORMAL MASS.
I CAN FIND NOTHING AT ALL
OUT OF THE ORDINARY.
WHAT ABOUT THE COMET
THAT ASTROPHYSICS
REPORTED?
WE'RE RUNNING CHECKS ON IT.
I'VE REACHED NO
CONCLUSIONS AS YET.
THE COMET WAS A ROGUE
AND HAS NEVER BEEN
INVESTIGATED.
CAPTAIN KIRK?
YES, COMMODORE.
FACILITIES
AT STARBASE 10 ARE
MUCH MORE COMPLETE
THAN THOSE
ONBOARD SHIP.
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT
YOUR INVESTIGATIONS
WOULD BE FACILITATED
IF WE PROCEEDED
THERE.
I ASSURE YOU ALL
COOPERATION.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW YOU'RE ANXIOUS
TO GET TO THE BASE,
BUT WE HAVE A FEW
FACILITIES OF
OUR OWN HERE.
I THINK
THE ENTERPRISE
WILL DO QUITE NICELY.
I'LL BE IN ENGINEERING,
MR. SPOCK.
MAINTAIN STANDARD ORBIT,
MR. SULU.
YOU ALREADY GAVE
THAT COMMAND, SIR.
OH? WELL...
FOLLOW IT.
LIEUTENANT GALWAY.
DOCTOR,
MAY I SPEAK TO YOU
FOR A MOMENT, PLEASE?
OF COURSE.
GO RIGHT AHEAD.
I KNOW THIS IS GOING TO
SOUND FOOLISH,
BUT I SEEM TO BE
HAVING A LITTLE
TROUBLE HEARING.
IT'S PROBABLY
NOTHING IMPORTANT.
I NEVER HAD TROUBLE
BEFORE.
WELL, DON'T WORRY
ABOUT IT.
PERHAPS A LITTLE
HYPERSONIC TREATMENT
MIGHT CLEAR IT UP.
THANK YOU.
PROGRESS REPORT,
MR. SPOCK.
ALL RESEARCH LINES
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
ASTRONOMICAL SECTION
REPORTS THAT A COMET
RECENTLY PASSED BY.
CHECK INTO THAT.
I'M DOING THAT, CAPTAIN,
AS PER YOUR PREVIOUS
ORDER.
YOU EXPRESSED THAT
EARLIER.
OH, YES. LET ME KNOW
WHAT YOU COME UP WITH.
I'LL BE IN SICK BAY.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
LAST ONE.
ROBERT JOHNSON.
CAUSE OF DEATH:
OLD AGE.
YOU DID WHAT YOU COULD.
WHICH ADDS UP TO
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
[INTERCOM]
Scotty: DR. McCOY,
THIS IS SCOTT.
MAY I COME UP
AND SEE YOU?
ALL YOU NEED ARE
VITAMINS, BUT YOU
CAN COME UP ANYHOW.
BONES. I BELIEVE
YOU'RE GETTING GRAY.
YOU TAKE OVER MY JOB
AND SEE WHAT HAPPENS
TO YOU.
HA HA! I SEE
WHAT YOU MEAN.
WHAT'S YOUR PROBLEM,
JIM?
SHOULDER.
JUST A TWINGE.
PROBABLY
MUSCULAR STRAIN.
OH. MM-HMM.
YOU'RE PROBABLY
RIGHT, DOCTOR.
I DON'T LIKE THE WAY
YOU'VE BEEN RUNNING
THIS SHIP LATELY.
ALL RIGHT, REPRIMAND
RECEIVED. GO AHEAD.
AH!
JIM, I THINK WE'D
BETTER RUN A COMPLETE
PHYSICAL ON YOU.
WHY?
JUST MUSCULAR STRAIN,
HMM?
NO, JIM.
IT'S ADVANCED ARTHRITIS.
IT'S SPREADING.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I CAN RUN IT THROUGH
AGAIN, BUT I'LL COME UP
WITH THE SAME THING.
[DOOR OPENS]
Kirk: SCOTTY!
Captain Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG
STARDATE 3579.4.
THE ENTERPRISE PERSONNEL
WHO BEAMED DOWN TO
THE PLANET'S SURFACE
DR. McCOY, ENGINEER SCOTT,
MR. SPOCK, LIEUTENANT GALWAY,
AND MYSELF
ARE ALL SHOWING DEFINITE
SIGNS OF AGING.
ONLY ENSIGN CHEKOV
APPEARS TO BE NORMAL.
REPORT, BONES.
ALL OF US WHO WENT DOWN
TO THE SURFACE, WITH THE
EXCEPTION OF CHEKOV,
ARE AGING AT
VARIOUS RATES,
APPROXIMATELY 30 YEARS
FOR EACH DAY.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S CAUSING IT--
VIRUS...BACTERIA...
OR EVIL SPIRITS--
BUT I'M TRYING
TO FIND OUT.
SPOCK, CAN I ASK
FOR SOME FIGURES?
BASED ON WHAT
DR. McCOY GAVE ME,
I ESTIMATE THAT PHYSICALLY
WE EACH HAVE LESS THAN
A WEEK TO LIVE.
ALSO, SINCE OUR MENTAL
FACULTIES ARE AGING FASTER
THAN OUR BODIES,
WE WILL BE LITTLE BETTER
THAN MENTAL VEGETABLES IN
A CONSIDERABLY LESSER TIME.
TOTAL SENILITY?
YES, CAPTAIN.
IN A VERY SHORT TIME.
WHAT A WAY TO DIE.
ALL RIGHT, I WANT ALL
THE RESEARCH FACILITIES,
ALL THE SCIENTIFIC
TECHNICIANS
TO START ROUND-THE-CLOCK
RESEARCH IMMEDIATELY.
I WANT THE ANSWERS
AND I WANT THE REMEDY,
AND START BY FINDING OUT
WHY CHEKOV HASN'T BEEN AFFECTED.
I'M DOING WHAT I CAN.
OH, YOU'RE PERFECTLY
HEALTHY.
I MUST DIFFER
WITH YOU, DOCTOR.
I'M HAVING DIFFICULTY
CONCENTRATING, WHICH IS
MOST DISTURBING.
MY EYESIGHT
APPEARS TO BE FAILING.
AND THE NORMAL TEMPERATURE
OF THE SHIP SEEMS TO ME
TO BE INCREASINGLY COLD.
I DID NOT SAY YOU WEREN'T
AFFECTED, MR. SPOCK.
YOU ARE PERFECTLY HEALTHY,
THAT IS FOR ANY NORMAL VULCAN
ON THE HIGH SIDE OF 100.
CAPTAIN, CAN I GO BACK
TO MY STATION?
YOU FEEL UP TO IT,
SCOTTY?
OF COURSE I DO.
I JUST NEED A WEE BIT
OF REST, THAT'S ALL.
YOU CAN LEAVE, TOO,
LIEUTENANT GALWAY.
LIEUTENANT GALWAY!
Galway: WHAT?
YOU SPOKE TO ME, DOCTOR?
YES, I SPOKE TO YOU. I SAID
THAT YOU CAN LEAVE, TOO, NOW.
WHY DON'T YOU GO ON
DOWN TO YOUR QUARTERS
AND GET SOME SLEEP.
[CRYING]
NO! I DON'T
WANT TO SLEEP!
CAN'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IF I SLEEP, WHAT WILL
I FIND WHEN I WAKE UP?
LIEUTENANT GALWAY.
ASSUME YOUR POSITION.
START YOUR DUTIES.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WHAT A STUPID PLACE
TO HANG A MIRROR!
SHE'S 10 YEARS
YOUNGER THAN I AM,
AND SHE LOOKS...
PEOPLE AGE NORMALLY
AT DIFFERENT SPEEDS, JIM.
WHY HASN'T HE AGED?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, I WANT TO KNOW!
IS IT HIS YOUTH,
HIS BLOOD TYPE,
HIS HERITAGE,
HIS GLANDS,
HIS GENES?
HIS GENES.
ALL RIGHT, NURSE,
PREPARE CHEKOV FOR
ANOTHER COMPLETE PHYSICAL.
COME ALONG, ENSIGN.
IT WON'T HURT...MUCH.
PROMISES.
A FEW YEARS AGO,
ON ALDEBERON 3,
MY HUSBAND AND I
TRIED VARIOUS
CARBOHYDRATE COMPOUNDS
TO SLOW DOWN
THIS GENERATION
OF PLANT LIFE.
WELL, THEN, TRY THAT,
DR. WALLACE.
TRY ANYTHING,
BUT DO IT QUICKLY.
YES, SIR.
I'LL BE ON THE BRIDGE.
KEEP ME POSTED AS TO CHEKOV.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
ON YOUR WAY TO THE
BIOCHEMISTRY LAB, DOCTOR.
WE'RE BOTH GO IN
THE SAME DIRECTION.
SO WE DO.
LOOK, WE KNOW
THE PROBLEM.
WE KNOW THE PROGRESS
OF THE AFFLICTION.
THEREFORE, ONCE WE FIND
THE PROPER LINE OF RESEARCH,
IT'S ONLY LOGICAL
WE FIND THE SOLUTION.
HA HA HA! SOUND LIKE
MY FIRST OFFICER.
NO PROBLEM
IS INSOLUBLE,
NOT EVEN OURS.
THAT DIDN'T SPRING
FROM LOGIC.
OUR SITUATION
DOESN'T HAVE ITS
ROOTS IN LOGIC.
THE HEART IS NOT
A LOGICAL ORGAN.
WHEN I MARRIED
THEODORE WALLACE,
I THOUGHT I WAS OVER YOU.
I WAS WRONG.
WHEN DID YOU
REALIZE THAT? TODAY?
WHAT?
HOW MUCH OLDER
IS YOUR HUSBAND?
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES THAT MAKE?
ANSWER ME.
26 YEARS.
THAT'S QUITE
A DIFFERENCE.
JIM, HE WAS
A BRILLIANT MAN.
WE WERE STATIONED
ON A LONELY OUTPOST.
WE WERE WORKING TOGETHER.
I DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT HIM.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT US.
LOOK AT ME.
WHAT DO YOU SEE?
I SEE CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK,
A MAN OF MORALITY,
DECENCY, HANDSOME
AND STRONG--
AND OLD...
AND RAPIDLY
GROWING OLDER.
JIM, PLEASE.
WHAT ARE YOU
OFFERING ME, JAN?
LOVE?
OR A GOING-AWAY PRESENT?
"GIVE SOME MORE
BLOOD, CHEKOV."
"THE NEEDLE WON'T
HURT, CHEKOV."
"TAKE OFF YOUR SHIRT,
CHEKOV."
"ROLL OVER, CHEKOV."
"BREATHE DEEPLY, CHEKOV."
"BLOOD SAMPLE, CHEKOV."
"MARROW SAMPLE, CHEKOV."
"SKIN SAMPLE, CHEKOV."
IF...IF I LIVE
LONG ENOUGH,
I'LL RUN OUT OF SAMPLES.
YOU'LL LIVE.
OH, YES, I'LL LIVE,
BUT I WON'T ENJOY IT.
MAINTAINING STANDARD
ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
BRING US OVER TO 20,000
PARAGEE, MR. SULU.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
Woman:
WILL YOU SIGN
THIS, SIR?
YEOMAN!
DO YOU HAVE A REASON
FOR BEING ON THE BRIDGE,
COMMODORE STOCKER?
I'D HOPED FOR A FEW WORDS
WITH YOU AT YOUR CONVENIENCE.
I HAVE VERY LITTLE TIME.
IF I MAY SAY SO, SIR,
WE HAVE A DUE DATE AT
STARBASE 10.
WE'RE GOING TO BE LATE.
I DON'T INTEND
TO LEAVE THIS AREA
UNTIL WE'VE FOUND
THE SOLUTION FOR
THIS PROBLEM.
CAPTAIN, I AM WATCHING
4 VERY VALUABLE
AND ONE ALMOST IRREPLACEABLE
MEMBERS OF THE STARFLEET
FAILING BEFORE MY EYES.
I WANT TO DO SOMETHING
TO HELP.
SINCE YOU'RE SO CONCERNED,
I'LL SEND A MESSAGE
TO STARBASE 10.
CAPTAIN, YOU SENT
SUCH A MESSAGE THIS MORNING.
OH.
YEOMAN!
WHERE IS THAT--
SIR?
FUEL CONSUMPTION REPORT?
I GAVE IT TO YOU,
SIR, AND YOU
SIGNED IT.
IF I HAD SIGNED IT,
I WOULDN'T ASK FOR IT,
NOW WOULD I?
YOUR SIGNATURE,
CAPTAIN.
I BELIEVE--
CAPTAIN. CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK,
I WAS JUST THINKING.
YES, SIR.
UNDERSTANDABLE.
YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO REPORT?
YES, SIR.
I BELIEVE WE HAVE
THE CAUSE OF THE AFFLICTION.
WHAT IS IT?
THE ORBIT OF GAMMA HYDRA 4
CARRIED THE PLANET
DIRECTLY THROUGH
THE COMET'S TRAIL.
ON CONVENTIONAL
RADIATION SETTINGS,
WE DISCOVERED NOTHING.
IN RESETTING OUR SENSORS
TO THE EXTREME LOWER
RANGE OF THE SCALE,
UNDETECTED RADIATION
APPEARED.
BELOW NORMAL
RADIATION LEVELS
BUT DEFINITELY PRESENT
AND UNDOUBTEDLY RESIDUE
FROM THE COMET.
GOOD, SPOCK.
WELL DONE.
LET'S GET THIS TO
DR. McCOY IMMEDIATELY.
OH, LIEUTENANT,
TAKE A MESSAGE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
AYE, SIR.
AND DUE TO THE PROXIMITY
OF THE ROMULANS,
BETTER USE CODE 2.
BUT CAPTAIN,
THE ROMULANS HAVE
BROKEN CODE 2.
IF YOU REMEMBER
THE LAST BULLETIN--
THEN USE CODE 3.
YES, SIR. CODE 3.
MESSAGE: KEY TO AFFLICTION
MAY BE COMET WHICH PASSED
BY GAMMA HYDRA 4.
SAID COMET IS NOW...
QUADRANT 448, SIR.
UH, QUADRANT...
ALL UNITS
ARE TO BE ALERTED
FOR COMPLETE ANALYSIS
OF RADIATION AND MEANS
FOUND TO NEUTRALIZE IT
COMES AS HIGHLY DANGEROUS.
KIRK, COMMANDING
ENTERPRISE...
IMMEDIATELY, LIEUTENANT.
LET'S GO.
AYE, SIR.
OH, MR. SULU.
INCREASE ORBIT TO
20,000 MILE PARAGEE.
YOU MEAN ANOTHER
20,000, CAPTAIN?
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY EACH ONE OF MY COMMANDS
IS BEING QUESTIONED.
NOW, DO AS YOU'RE
TOLD, MR. SULU.
MR. SULU, WHAT IS
OUR PRESENT POSITION?
ORBITING AT
20,000, SIR.
MAINTAIN.
MAINTAINING, SIR.
RADIATION. WELL, THAT'S
AS GOOD AN ANSWER AS ANY,
BUT WHY DIDN'T WE
KNOW ABOUT IT EARLIER?
POSSIBLY, DOCTOR,
BECAUSE MY THINKING PROCESS
IS NOT AS EFFICIENT
AS BEFORE.
RUN THIS THROUGH,
DOCTOR.
ALL RIGHT, BONES.
I'M GOING UP TO
THE BRIDGE.
KEEP ME POSTED.
SPOCK?
I HAVE A QUESTION
FOR THE DOCTOR.
DOCTOR, SHIP'S TEMPERATURE
IS INCREASINGLY
UNCOMFORTABLE FOR ME.
I'VE ADJUSTED THE
ENVIRONMENT IN MY QUARTERS
TO 125 DEGREES,
WHICH IS AT LEAST
TOLERABLE.
HOWEVER, I--
WELL...I SEE I'M NOT
GONNA BE MAKING ANY
HOUSE CALLS ON YOU.
I WONDERED IF PERHAPS
THERE WAS SOMETHING WHICH COULD
LOWER MY SENSITIVITY TO COLD.
I'M NOT A MAGICIAN, SPOCK,
JUST AN OLD COUNTRY DOCTOR.
YES...
AS I ALWAYS
SUSPECTED.
DR. McCOY, NONE OF OUR
USUAL RADIATION THERAPIES
WILL HAVE ANY EFFECT
ON HIS RADIATION SICKNESS.
WELL, WE JUST START
OVER, THAT'S ALL.
WE WORK HARDER,
FASTER,
AND WE START
COMPLETELY FROM SCRATCH
IF WE HAVE TO,
BUT WE FIND SOMETHING.
Commodore: SPOCK.
CAN I HAVE
A WORD WITH YOU?
COMMODORE.
MR. SPOCK, A STARSHIP
CAN FUNCTION WITH A
CHIEF ENGINEER,
CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER,
EVEN THE FIRST OFFICER
UNDER PHYSICAL HARM.
BUT IT IS DISASTROUS
TO HAVE A COMMANDING
OFFICER WHOSE CONDITION
IS ANY LESS
THAN PERFECTION.
I AM AWARE OF THAT.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND ME.
MY ADMIRATION FOR
CAPTAIN KIRK IS
UNBOUNDED.
HE IS A GREAT OFFICER.
BUT MR. SPOCK, I...
I NEED YOUR HELP
AND YOUR COOPERATION.
FOR WHAT, SIR?
I WOULD LIKE YOU
TO TAKE OVER COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
ON WHAT GROUNDS,
COMMODORE?
ON THE GROUNDS
THAT THE CAPTAIN,
BECAUSE OF HIS
AFFLICTION,
IS UNABLE TO PERFORM
HIS DUTIES.
NEED I REMIND YOU, SIR,
THAT I, TOO, CONTRACTED
THE SAME AFFLICTION?
YES, BUT YOU'RE
A VULCAN.
YOU HAVE A MUCH
GREATER LIFESPAN.
YOU SHOW THE EFFECTS
TO A MUCH SMALLER
DEGREE.
I'M HALF HUMAN, SIR.
MY PHYSICAL REFLEXES
ARE DOWN. MY MENTAL
CAPACITY IS REDUCED.
I TIRE EASILY.
NO. SIR. I AM NOT
FIT FOR COMMAND.
WELL, IF YOU ARE NOT,
WITH YOUR VULCAN
PHYSIQUE,
THEN OBVIOUSLY CAPTAIN
KIRK CANNOT BE.
SIR, I DO HAVE
DUTIES TO PERFORM.
MR. SPOCK.
I DO NOT LIKE WHAT
I'M ABOUT TO SAY,
BUT REGULATIONS
DEMAND IT.
AND AS A STARFLEET
FLAG OFFICER, I MUST
FOLLOW REGULATIONS.
AS SECOND IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
YOU MUST CONVENE
AN EXTRAORDINARY
COMPETENCY HEARING.
I RESIST THAT
SUGGESTION, COMMODORE.
IT'S NOT A MATTER
OF CHOICE.
WHEN A CAPTAIN IS UNFIT,
PHYSICALLY OR MENTALLY,
A COMPETENCY HEARING
IS MANDATORY.
PLEASE DON'T MAKE ME
QUOTE A REGULATION
WHICH YOU KNOW
AS WELL AS I DO.
VERY WELL, SIR.
HEARING SHALL CONVENE
AT 1400 HOURS.
NOW, THIS ISN'T
GONNA HURT A BIT.
THAT'S WHAT YOU SAID
THE LAST TIME.
DID IT HURT?
YES.
UHH!
OHH!
BONES.
SHE'S DEAD.
HER METABOLISM CAUSED
HER TO AGE MORE RAPIDLY
THAN THE REST OF US,
BUT THE SAME THING'S
GONNA HAPPEN TO US
UNLESS...
HOW LONG HAVE WE
GOT, BONES?
OH...MATTER OF DAYS,
PERHAPS HOURS.
Spock: LET IT READ THAT THIS
COMPETENCY HEARING WAS ORDERED
BY COMMODORE STOCKER
AND RELUCTANTLY CALLED
BY MYSELF.
LET IT ALSO READ
THAT I CONSIDER IT
INVALID.
MR. SPOCK,
MAY I MAKE A STATEMENT?
I HAVE HAD TO RESORT TO
THESE LEGAL GROUNDS IN ORDER
TO SAVE THE LIVES
OF SOME VERY VALUABLE
MEMBERS OF THE STARFLEET.
I HAVE TRIED TO CONVINCE
CAPTAIN KIRK OF THE NECESSITY
OF PROCEEDING TO STARBASE 10,
BUT I'VE BEEN OVERRULED
IN EACH CASE.
THE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR THIS HEARING IS MINE.
ON THE CONTRARY,
COMMODORE.
AS PRESIDING OFFICER
AND AS SECOND IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
THE RESPONSIBILITY
IS MINE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
YOU LIKE TO MAKE
A STATEMENT?
YES, I WOULD LIKE
TO MAKE A STATEMENT.
I AM THE CAPTAIN
OF THIS SHIP
AND AM TOTALLY CAPABLE
OF COMMANDING HER.
NOW LET'S CALL THIS
WHOLE THING OFF AND
GET BACK TO WORK.
IT'S QUITE IMPOSSIBLE,
CAPTAIN.
REGULATIONS ARE
QUITE SPECIFIC.
YOU ARE ENTITLED TO
DIRECT EXAMINATION
OF ALL WITNESSES
IMMEDIATELY AFTER
THE BOARD HAS
QUESTIONED THEM.
VERY KIND OF YOU,
SPOCK.
MR. SULU,
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
SERVED WITH CAPTAIN KIRK?
TWO YEARS, SIR.
TO YOUR KNOWLEDGE, HAS HE
EVER HAD ANY DIFFICULTY
MAKING DECISIONS?
NO, SIR.
DID HE ORDER YOU
TO MAINTAIN STANDARD ORBIT
AROUND GAMMA HYDRA 4?
YES, SIR.
DID HE NOT,
SEVERAL MINUTES LATER,
REPEAT THAT ORDER?
YES, SIR.
DID HE ORDER YOU
TO INCREASE ORBIT?
YES, SIR.
AND NOT SEVERAL
MINUTES LATER REPEAT
THAT ORDER?
HE DID NOT!
WHEN I GIVE AN ORDER,
I EXPECT IT TO BE OBEYED.
I DON'T HAVE TO
REPEAT MYSELF.
MR. SULU...
PLEASE
ANSWER THE QUESTION.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN KIRK
REPEATED HIS ORDER.
THANK YOU, MR. SULU.
YEOMAN ATKINS...
YOU HANDED CAPTAIN KIRK
A FUEL CONSUMPTION REPORT
IN THE PRESENCE
OF WITNESSES
WHICH HE READ AND SIGNED.
IS THAT CORRECT?
SIR, HE HAD MORE
IMPORTANT THINGS
ON HIS MIND.
YEOMAN,
YOU WILL SIMPLY
ANSWER THE QUESTION.
I...
I GUESS HE FORGOT
HE'D SIGNED IT.
YOU GUESS.
HE'D FORGOT
HE'D SIGNED IT.
THANK YOU, YEOMAN.
YOU MAY LEAVE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA...
I HAVE HERE A BULLETIN
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND
WHICH STATES THAT
THE ROMULANS HAVE
BROKEN CODE 2.
ARE THESE YOUR
INITIALS WHICH APPEAR
AT THE BOTTOM?
THEY ARE.
AND WHOSE INITIALS
ARE THOSE
WHICH APPEAR DIRECTLY
BELOW YOURS?
THOSE OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
DID CAPTAIN KIRK
ASK YOU TO SEND
A MESSAGE
ABOUT THE COMET
WHICH PASSED
GAMMA HYDRA 4?
HE DID.
USING CODE 2.
OH, YES, BUT HE
CHANGED IT TO CODE 3.
AFTER YOU REMINDED HIM
THAT THE ROMULANS
HAD BROKEN CODE 2.
YES.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
DR. McCOY...
DR. McCOY!
YE-YES, SPOCK?
WHAT IS IT?
SEVERAL HOURS AGO,
AT THE REQUEST
OF THIS BOARD,
YOU RAN A COMPLETE
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
I DID.
MEDICAL BANKS,
COMPUTE
AND DESCRIBE SUBJECT'S
PHYSICAL AGE,
USING ESTABLISHED NORMS
AS COMPARATIVE BASE.
WORKING. SUBJECT'S
PHYSICAL AGE
BASED ON PHYSIOLOGICAL
PROFILE.
BETWEEN 60 AND 72.
AGING RAPIDLY.
NO, I'M 34--
I'M 34 YEARS OLD.
THE COMPUTER DIFFERS
WITH YOU, CAPTAIN.
DR. McCOY...
YES.
WILL YOU GIVE US
YOUR PROFESSIONAL
EVALUATION
OF CAPTAIN KIRK'S
PRESENT PHYSICAL CONDITION?
OH...CAPTAIN KIRK
IS SUFFERING FROM A...
A PECULIAR
PHYSICAL DEGENERATION
WHICH STRONGLY
RESEMBLES AGING.
IS NOT HIS MENTAL
CAPACITY DEGENERATING
EVEN MORE RAPIDLY?
YES, YES, BUT HE'S
A BETTER MAN RIGHT NOW--
DOCTOR, YOU HEARD
THE COMPUTER'S ANALYSIS
OF CAPTAIN KIRK'S
PHYSICAL AGE.
DO YOU AGREE WITH IT?
THESE BLASTED MACHINES,
SPOCK.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE
WITH A MACHINE.
DO YOU AGREE WITH IT,
DOCTOR?
YES.
YES, I DO...AGREE.
AND I AM SORRY, JIM.
THIS BOARD HAS
NO FURTHER QUESTIONS...
UNLESS YOU,
COMMODORE STOCKER,
HAVE SOMETHING
THAT YOU WOULD
LIKE TO ADD.
NO. I AM...
QUITE SATISFIED,
MR. SPOCK.
DO YOU WISH TO CALL
ANY WITNESSES,
CAPTAIN KIRK?
HEH HEH HEH.
I AM PERFECTLY CAPABLE
OF SPEAKING IN MY
OWN DEFENSE, MR. SPOCK.
CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SUGGEST--
NO, NO, NO.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SPOCK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S ONLY
ONE REASON...
AND ONE REASON ALONE...
FOR HAVING THIS...
HEARING.
I REFUSED TO LEAVE
GAMMA HYDRA 2.
GAMMA HYDRA 4,
CAPTAIN.
YES. A SLIP OF THE TONGUE.
CAPTAIN, YOUR INABILITY
TO REMEMBER HAVING
GIVEN COMMANDS,
READING AND SIGNING
IMPORTANT ORDERS
AND THEN
FORGETTING THEM,
YOUR PHYSICAL ANALYSIS
AS COMPILED BY
OUR OWN CHIEF SURGEON--
ALL THESE THINGS
WOULD APPEAR TO BE
IRREFUTABLE PROOF OF
FAILING PHYSICAL AND
MENTAL CONDITIONS.
SO I'M A LITTLE CONFUSED.
WHO WOULDN'T BE
AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
MY SHIP'S IN TROUBLE,
MY SENIOR OFFICERS ARE ILL.
AND THIS NONSENSE
ABOUT A COMPETENCY HEARING
IS ENOUGH TO MIX UP
ANY MAN.
TRYING TO RELIEVE A CAPTAIN
OF HIS COMMAND IS...
WELL, THAT'S...
THAT'S...
SPOCK...
I WOULDN'T HAVE
BELIEVED IT OF YOU.
ALL RIGHT,
ASK ME QUESTIONS.
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHAT I'M CAPABLE OF.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH MY MEMORY.
GO AHEAD!
ASK ME ANYTHING!
WE'RE IN ORBIT
AROUND GAMMA HYDRA 2,
RIGHT?
ANYHOW,
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THERE'S A LOT MORE
TO RUNNING A STARSHIP
THAN ANSWERING
A LOT OF FOOL QUESTIONS.
A LOT MORE.
GO AHEAD.
ASK ME QUESTIONS.
WE HAVE NO MORE
QUESTIONS, CAPTAIN.
ASK ME ANYTHING.
HEH HEH HEH.
ANYTHING.
THERE'LL BE
NO MORE QUESTIONS,
CAPTAIN.
IF YOU WOULD LEAVE THE ROOM
SO THE BOARD CAN VOTE...
GOOD IDEA.
GET THIS STUPID
VOTING OVER WITH
SO I CAN GET BACK
TO RUNNING THE SHIP.
THE MOST FOOL THING
I EVER HEARD OF.
A COMPETENCY HEARING
WHEN THERE'S WORK TO BE DONE.
I'LL BE IN MY QUARTERS...
AWAITING YOUR DECISION.
WELL, SINCE
THE SENIOR OFFICERS
ARE INCAPABLE
AND I AM OF FLAG RANK,
I AM FORCED BY REGULATIONS
TO ASSUME COMMAND.
SIR, YOU HAVE NEVER
COMMANDED A STARSHIP.
WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE,
MR. SPOCK,
A JUNIOR OFFICER
WITH FAR LESS EXPERIENCE
THAN I HAVE?
THE DANGER
FROM THE ROMULANS--
MR. SPOCK, WE HAVE TO
SAVE THESE PEOPLE.
MR. SULU...
SET A DIRECT COURSE
FOR STARBASE 10.
WARP 5.
ACROSS THE NEUTRAL ZONE?
IMMEDIATELY, MR. SULU.
ALL OFFICERS ARE
TO RETURN TO THEIR POSTS.
SPOCK?
YES, CAPTAIN.
SO...
I'VE BEEN RELIEVED.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
YES.
YOU SHOULD'VE BEEN
A PROSECUTING ATTORNEY.
REGULATIONS REQUIRE--
REGULATIONS.
DON'T GIVE ME REGULATIONS.
YOU'VE WANTED COMMAND
ALL ALONG.
FIRST LITTLE EXCUSE
YOU GET--
CAPTAIN, I HAVE NOT
ASSUMED COMMAND.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOU'VE--YOU'VE
NOT ASSUMED COMMAND?
I SUFFER THE SAME
AFFLICTION
AS YOU, SIR.
IF YOU'RE NOT IN COMMAND,
WHO IS?
COMMODORE STOCKER.
STOCKER?
ARE YOU CRAZY?
HE'S NEVER HAD
A FIELD COMMAND.
MR. SCOTT WAS
UNFIT FOR COMMAND.
COMMODORE STOCKER
IS RANKING OFFICER--
NO! DON'T TALK TO ME
ABOUT RANK!
THE MAN'S
A CHAIR-BOUND PAPER-PUSHER.
I ORDER YOU
TO TAKE COMMAND.
I CANNOT, CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU REFUSING
A DIRECT ORDER?
NO, SIR.
ONLY COMMODORE STOCKER
CAN GIVE A COMMAND ORDER
ONBOARD THIS SHIP.
YOU TRAITOROUS...
DISLOYAL...
YOU STAB ME IN THE BACK
THE FIRST CHANCE YOU GET.
SPOCK...
GET OUT.
I NEVER WANT TO
HAVE TO LOOK AT YOU AGAIN.
JAN...
JAN.
OH, JIM. I'M SORRY.
TRULY I AM.
I MADE A FOOL OF MYSELF
IN THERE.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE
LET THEM CONFUSE ME...
RATTLE ME.
EVERYBODY UNDERSTOOD.
BUT I'M NOT OLD...
JAN.
I'M NOT.
[WHEEZING]
A FEW MUSCULAR ACHES
DOESN'T MAKE A MAN OLD.
AND YOU
DON'T RUN A STARSHIP
WITH YOUR ARMS.
YOU RUN IT
WITH YOUR HEAD.
MY BRAIN'S AS SHARP
AS IT EVER WAS.
A SIMPLE CASE
OF RADIATION POISONING,
AND THEY RELIEVE ME
OF MY COMMAND.
I ADMIT I'M GETTING
A LITTLE GRAY,
BUT RADIATION
WILL DO THAT TO YOU.
OH, JIM,
WILL YOU FORGIVE ME--
JAN, YOU KNOW ME.
LOOK AT ME CLOSELY.
TELL ME.
AM I GETTING OLD?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
IT WOULD SEEM TO BE
THE PLACE
WHERE I CAN BE
OF THE MOST USE.
MAYBE YOU'D LIKE TO
RELIEVE DR. McCOY.
WHAT ABOUT CHEKOV?
NOTHING.
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
BONES,
THERE HAS TO BE.
WE...BEAMED DOWN
TOGETHER.
WE WERE ON THE
SURFACE TOGETHER.
THE SAME SPOT.
WE WERE TOGETHER
ALL THE TIME!
NO, NOT ALL THE TIME,
CAPTAIN.
HE LEFT US
FOR A FEW MOMENTS.
HE LEFT US?
HE LEFT US.
HE WENT INTO
THE BUILDING.
SPOCK...
SOMETHING HAPPENED.
YES.
YES, INDEED, CAPTAIN.
DOCTOR,
YOU REMEMBER--
HE WAS SCARED!
HE SAW THE DEAD BODY
AND HE RAN OUT
OF THE BUILDING.
AND HE WAS SCARED TO DEATH.
YES, YES.
NOW THAT WOULD BE.
RIGHT. SCARED.
HEART BEATS FASTER,
BREATH GETS SHORT,
AND THERE'S
COLD SWEATS
AND
ADRENALINE FLOWS.
ADRENAL ACTIVITY.
NOW HOLD ON
JUST A MINUTE.
THERE WAS SOMETHING
THAT I READ ONCE.
IT WAS...
ANCIENT HISTORY...
JUST AFTER
THE ATOMIC AGE...
UH...
USED FOR
RADIATION SICKNESS.
ADRENALINE.
DOCTOR, HYRONALINE
IS THE SPECIFIC ACCEPTED
FOR ALL RADIATION SICKNESS.
YES, YES. NOW.
BUT BEFORE,
ADRENALINE.
HIGHLY PROMISING.
EARLY RESEARCH...
BUT THEY ABANDONED
IT WHEN HYRONALINE
WAS DISCOVERED.
QUITE POSSIBLE,
DOCTOR.
PERHAPS...
A SUFFICIENTLY
EFFICACIOUS COMPOUND
COULD BE DEVELOPED.
DON'T JUST STAND THERE
JAWING, SPOCK.
YOU AND DR. WALLACE
GET CRACKING.
ENTERING ROMULAN
NEUTRAL ZONE,
SIR.
[BEEPING]
ALL SENSORS
ON MAXIMUM.
THANK YOU, MR. SULU.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
LET ME KNOW IF WE
CONTACT ANY ROMULAN.
[CRASH]
I THINK WE JUST
MADE CONTACT, SIR.
ROMULANS APPROACHING
FROM BOTH SIDES.
THEY'RE
BRACKETED, SIR.
ENGINEERING
WANTS INSTRUCTIONS, SIR.
COMMODORE STOCKER,
WHAT ARE YOUR ORDERS?
[ALARMS SOUNDING]
COMMODORE!
[CRASH]
I'M GOING
UP TO THE BRIDGE.
NO, JIM. YOU CAN'T
DO IT.
I HAVE TO GO TO
THE BRIDGE.
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
NURSE!
DR. WALLACE!
LET ME GO!
JIM,
TAKE IT EASY.
WE'RE UNDER ATTACK.
I HAVE TO GO
TO THE BRIDGE.
I'VE GOT TO GO
KEEP TRYING
TO RAISE THE ROMULANS.
I'M TRYING,
COMMODORE.
IF I COULD TALK TO THEM,
EXPLAIN TO THEM
WHY WE VIOLATED
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THE ROMULANS ARE
NOTORIOUS FOR
NOT LISTENING
TO EXPLANATIONS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
IS RIGHT, SIR.
WE'VE TANGLED
WITH THEM BEFORE.
GREENHORN...
UP THERE
RUINING MY SHIP.
IF I HAVE TO
GIVE YOU A SHOT--
JIM, YOU JUST
LAY QUIET.
YOU CAN'T DO NO GOOD.
WE'RE BOTH THROUGH.
NO.
MY SHIP.
[CRASH]
DOCTOR, WE MADE THE
NECESSARY COMPUTATIONS
AND PRODUCED THIS SERUM.
IT IS CRUDE
AND DANGEROUS,
BUT WE HAD NO TIME
FOR REFINEMENTS.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S...LET'S GO.
IT COULD CURE
OR KILL, DOCTOR.
DON'T GIVE ME
ANY VULCAN DETAILS,
SPOCK.
JUST
GIVE ME THE SHOT.
NO.
I'LL TAKE THE FIRST SHOT.
YOU CAN'T.
[CRASH]
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK
THIS SHIP
CAN TAKE THE POUNDING?
I'VE GOT TO GET UP THERE.
JIM,
IT COULD KILL YOU.
I'LL DIE ANYWAY.
DO IT!
DR. WALLACE...
GIVE HIM THE SHOT.
QUICKLY.
AAH! OOH! AH!
Sulu:
SIR, THEY'VE
FIRED ANOTHER.
[CRASH]
AAH!
AAH...OWWW...
WELL, WELL,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
THE AGEING PROCESS
HAS STOPPED.
HIS BODILY FUNCTIONS
ARE GETTING STRONGER.
SIR, I'VE TRIED ALL KNOWN
HAILING FREQUENCIES.
THEY SIMPLY IGNORE US.
OPINION, MR. SULU.
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE US.
THEY KNOW OUR SHIELDS
WILL GIVE OUT.
WELL, THEN, WE
HAVE NO ALTERNATIVE
BUT TO SURRENDER.
SIR...
THE ROMULANS
DO NOT TAKE CAPTIVES.
Sulu:
WE'RE LOSING
POWER, SIR.
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO?
I'VE GOT TO DO SOMETHING.
REPORT, MR. SULU.
WE'RE SURROUNDED BY
ROMULAN VESSELS.
MAXIMUM OF 10.
RANGE--
50-100,000 KILOMETERS.
ENGINEERING,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
I WANT FULL
EMERGENCY POWER.
I WANT EVERYTHING
IN ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
I WANT THE WARP-DRIVE
ENGINES ON FULL STANDBY.
KIRK OUT.
OPEN UP
A SPECIAL CHANNEL TO
STARFLEET COMMAND.
CODE 2.
BUT, CAPTAIN, CODE--
THAT'S AN ORDER,
LIEUTENANT.
CODE 2.
YES, CAPTAIN.
MESSAGE--FROM ENTERPRISE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND
THIS SECTOR.
I HAVE INADVERTENTLY
ENCROACHED UPON
ROMULAN NEUTRAL ZONE,
SURROUNDED AND UNDER
HEAVY ROMULAN ATTACK.
ESCAPE IMPOSSIBLE,
SHIELDS FAILING.
WILL IMPLEMENT DESTRUCT ORDER
USING COBRAMITE DEVICE
RECENTLY INSTALLED.
SINCE THIS WILL RESULT
IN THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE ENTERPRISE
AND ALL MATTER WITHIN
A 200,000-KILOMETER DIAMETER
AND ESTABLISH
A CORRESPONDING DEAD ZONE,
ALL FEDERATION SHIPS
WILL AVOID THIS AREA
FOR THE NEXT
FOUR SOLAR YEARS.
EXPLOSION WILL TAKE PLACE
IN ONE MINUTE.
KIRK, COMMANDING
ENTERPRISE, OUT.
MR. SULU,
COURSE 1-8-8 DEGREES,
MARK 14.
SPEED...WARP FACTOR 8.
STAND BY.
STANDING BY, SIR.
ROMULANS GIVING GROUND,
CAPTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY, THEY TAPPED IN
AS YOU EXPECTED THEM TO.
A LOGICAL ASSUMPTION,
MR. SPOCK.
ARE THEY
STILL RETREATING?
YES, SIR.
GOOD.
ALL HANDS, STAND BY.
WARP FACTOR 8...NOW.
THE ROMULANS WERE
CAUGHT OFF-GUARD,
CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE FALLING BEHIND.
ARE WE OUT OF RANGE,
MR. SULU?
YES, SIR, AND OUT OF
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
SECURE FROM RED ALERT.
ADJUST A NEW COURSE--
2-5-7 DEGREES, MARK 3,
HEADING FOR STARBASE 10.
2-5-7 DEGREES,
MARK 3.
CAPTAIN, I...
JUST WANTED TO ASSURE YOU
THAT I DID WHAT
I THOUGHT BEST TO SAVE
BOTH YOU AND THE MEN.
NOTED. YOU SHOULD KNOW,
HOWEVER, THERE'S VERY
LITTLE A STARBASE CAN DO
THAT A STARSHIP CAN'T.
IF I MAY SAY SO,
CAPTAIN,
I'M NOW QUITE AWARE
OF WHAT A STARSHIP
CAN DO...
WITH THE RIGHT MAN
AT THE HELM.
[DOOR OPENS]
YOU'RE LOOKING GOOD,
DOC.
FEELING FINE.
SO IS SCOTTY.
SERUM WORKED.
PULLED A MUSCLE
DURING THE REACTION,
BUT OTHERWISE
HE'S FEELING FINE.
AND YOURSELF?
VERY WELL. A FEW BRUISES
HERE AND THERE.
OH.
ANYTIME YOU'RE
READY, MR. SPOCK.
I AM QUITE READY NOW,
DOCTOR.
BECAUSE OF
YOUR VULCAN PHYSIQUE,
I HAVE PREPARED
AN EXTREMELY POTENT
SHOT FOR YOU.
HOWEVER,
I THOUGHT YOU
MIGHT LIKE TO KNOW
I'VE REMOVED
ALL THE BREAKABLES
FROM SICK BAY.
THAT'S VERY CONSIDERATE
OF YOU, DOCTOR.
I THOUGHT YOU'D
BE PLEASED TO HEAR THAT.
WELL, GENTLEMEN,
ALL AND ALL,
AN EXPERIENCE
WE'LL REMEMBER
IN OUR OLD AGE...
WHICH WON'T BE
FOR SOME WHILE, I HOPE.
TAKE OVER, MR. SULU.
STEADY AS SHE GOES.
STEADY AS SHE GOES,
CAPTAIN.
I THOUGHT I SAID THAT.