OUR SCANNER SURVEY
WAS CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
THERE IT IS--
PURE TRITANIUM.
FANTASTIC.
20 TIMES AS HARD
AS DIAMONDS.
21.4 TIMES AS HARD,
TO BE EXACT.
[BEEP BEEP]
SCOTTY, YOU CAN
MARK THIS VEIN
AS CONFIRMED.
INFORM STARFLEET
I RECOMMEND
THAT THEY DISPATCH
A SURVEY VESSEL
IMMEDIATELY.
Scotty:
ACKNOWLEDGED, CAPTAIN.
THEY'LL SEND
A VESSEL FAST ENOUGH
FOR THIS RICH A FIND.
WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO BREAK IT, CAPTAIN.
I'LL PHASER OFF A SPECIMEN.
LESLIE.
[SNIFF SNIFF]
DO YOU SMELL THAT?
A SWEET ODOR
LIKE HONEY.
IT WAS YEARS AGO...
ON ANOTHER PLANET...
A THING WITH A...
AN ODOR LIKE THAT.
WE'RE IN THE GROWING SEASON
IN THIS HEMISPHERE
OF THIS PLANET, CAPTAIN.
THERE ARE DOUBTLESS
MANY POLLEN AROMAS.
RIZZO.
YES, SIR?
TAKE YOUR MEN.
MAKE A SWING
AROUND OUR PERIMETER.
SCAN FOR DI-KIRONIUM
IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
SET YOUR PHASERS
ON DISRUPTER-B.
IF YOU SEE
ANY GASEOUS CLOUD,
FIRE IMMEDIATELY.
YOU'RE ON RED ALERT.
MAKE A SWEEP.
[BEEP BEEP]
Scotty:
READY TO BEAM BACK
ABOARD, CAPTAIN?
NEGATIVE, SCOTTY,
WE'RE CHECKING
SOMETHING OUT.
THE U.S.S. "YORKTOWN"
IS EXPECTING
TO RENDEZVOUS WITH US
IN LESS THAN 8 HOURS,
CAPTAIN.
THAT DOESN'T GIVE US
MUCH TIME.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
CONTINUE
STANDING BY.
KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, DI-KIRONIUM
EXISTS ONLY IN
LABORATORY EXPERIMENTS.
[SNIFFING]
IT'S GONE.
I COULD HAVE
BEEN WRONG.
THE LAST TIME
I CAUGHT AN ODOR
LIKE THAT...
WAS 11 YEARS AGO.
IT SEEMED TO READ
DI-KIRONIUM
FOR A MINUTE,
AND THEN I LOST IT.
[TRICORDER BEEPING]
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
SOMETHING OUT THERE
KNOWS I'M SCANNING IT.
IT'S KIND OF--
KEEPS CHANGING ITSELF
INTO SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
THAT ISN'T POSSIBLE.
NOTHING CAN DO THAT.
[CHOKING]
CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN...
THERE'S A STRANGE CLOUD,
SIR. IT'S--
[CHOKING]
CLOUD...CLOUD.
FIRE INTO IT IMMEDIATELY.
[CHOKING]
HELP.
SPOCK.
DEAD...
AND YOU'LL FIND
EVERY RED CORPUSCLE
GONE FROM THEIR BODY.
RIZZO'S ALIVE...BARELY.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTTY,
LOCK IN ON US.
MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
YOU THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT IT WAS, CAPTAIN?
SOMETHING THAT
CAN'T POSSIBLY EXIST...
BUT IT DOES.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3619.2.
WITH THE MYSTERIOUS DEATH
OF TWO CREWMEN,
ALL PERSONNEL
ON THE PLANET
HAVE BEEN EVACUATED
BACK TO THE SHIP.
AUTOPSY REPORT, DOCTOR.
HOW'S ENSIGN RIZZO?
STILL UNCONSCIOUS,
SIR.
TRANSFUSIONS?
CONTINUING AS RAPIDLY
AS POSSIBLE.
HIS BLOOD COUNT IS STILL
60% LESS THAN NORMAL.
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
SPOCK HERE. READY
TO LEAVE ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
CUTTING IN
IF I MAY, CAPTAIN.
THE U.S.S. "YORKTOWN"
IS EXPECTING
TO RENDEZVOUS WITH US
IN LESS THAN 7 HOURS.
THEN YOU'LL INFORM THEM THAT
WE MIGHT BE A LITTLE LATE.
JIM, THE "YORKTOWN"'S
SHIP'S SURGEON
WILL WANT TO KNOW
HOW LATE.
THOSE VACCINES HE'S
TRANSFERRING TO US
ARE HIGHLY PERISHABLE.
SPOCK AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
THOSE MEDICAL SUPPLIES
ARE BADLY NEEDED
ON PLANET THETA 7.
THEY ARE EXPECTING US
TO GET THEM THERE ON TIME.
GENTLEMEN, WE ARE
REMAINING IN ORBIT
UNTIL I FIND OUT
MORE ABOUT THOSE DEATHS,
ON MY RESPONSIBILITY.
I AM PERFECTLY AWARE
THAT IT MIGHT COST LIVES
ON THETA 7.
KIRK OUT.
AUTOPSY REPORT.
YOU SAW
THEIR COLOR.
THERE WASN'T
A RED CORPUSCLE LEFT
IN THEIR BODIES.
MARKS, CUTS,
INCISIONS OF ANY KIND?
NOT A ONE.
WHAT HAPPENED
IS MEDICALLY IMPOSSIBLE.
I SUGGEST YOU LOOK
AT THE RECORD TAPES
OF PAST SIMILAR OCCURRENCES.
YOU'LL FIND
THE U.S.S. "FARRAGUT"
LISTS CASUALTIES
11 YEARS AGO
FROM EXACTLY THE SAME
IMPOSSIBLE CAUSES.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I'LL CHECK THOSE TAPES
IMMEDIATELY.
FIRST...
CAN YOU BRING ENSIGN RIZZO
TO CONSCIOUSNESS
FOR A MOMENT?
YES, BUT IT--
WILL IT HURT HIM
IF YOU DO SO?
IN HIS
PRESENT CONDITION,
I DON'T THINK IT WOULD
MAKE MUCH DIFFERENCE.
THEN DO SO.
TRANSFUSION
COMPLETED, SIR.
HIS PULSE
AND RESPIRATION
ARE STILL
FAR BELOW NORMAL.
GIVE HIM ONE CC
OF CORDAZINE, NURSE.
YES, SIR.
RIZZO...
THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
DO YOU REMEMBER
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
R-R-REMEMBER...
I'M COLD.
I'M SO COLD.
YOU WERE ATTACKED
BY SOMETHING.
WHEN IT HAPPENED...
DID YOU NOTICE...
AN ODOR OF ANY KIND?
RIZZO.
RIZZO!
DO YOU REMEMBER
A SICKLY-SWEET ODOR?
DID YOU SMELL IT?
YES.
A SMELL...
A STRANGE SMELL.
IT WAS LIKE...
LIKE--LIKE
BEING SMOTHERED...
IN HONEY.
DID YOU FEEL...
A PRESENCE,
AN INTELLIGENCE?
IT WAS--
IT WAS TRYING
TO DRAW STRENGTH
FROM US.
I FELT IT.
IT WAS...
TH...TH...
IT WAS THERE.
HE'S BEGINNING
TO SLEEP AGAIN, JIM.
I CAN'T RISK
ANOTHER SHOT.
HE'S ALREADY TOLD ME
WHAT I WANTED TO KNOW.
I WOULDN'T DEPEND TOO MUCH
ON WHAT HE SAYS
IN THAT HALF-CONSCIOUS STATE.
HE COULD BE DREAMING,
SAYING WHAT HE THOUGHT
HE WANTED YOU TO HEAR.
YOU CHECK THOSE
RECORD TAPES.
I WANT YOUR MEDICAL ANALYSIS
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
WELL,
WHAT'S WITH THE CAPTAIN?
I'VE NEVER SEEN HIM
LIKE THAT BEFORE.
I INTEND TO FIND OUT.
I'LL BE IN
THE MEDICAL RECORD LIBRARY.
OH, CAPTAIN.
SUBSPACE MESSAGE
FROM STARFLEET.
THEY'RE INQUIRING--
NOT NOW, LIEUTENANT.
HAVE THE SECURITY
DUTY OFFICER
REPORT TO ME
ON THE BRIDGE
IMMEDIATELY.
AYE, SIR.
SPOCK?
CONTINUING SCANNING,
CAPTAIN.
STILL NO READINGS
OF LIFE FORMS
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
LET'S ASSUME
THAT IT'S SOMETHING
SO COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
THAT OUR SENSORS
WOULD NOT IDENTIFY IT
AS A LIFE FORM.
YOU MENTIONED
DI-KIRONIUM, CAPTAIN.
SUPPOSE IT WAS COMPOSED
OF THAT RARE ELEMENT...
A STRANGE,
GASEOUS CREATURE.
I HAVE SCANNED
FOR THAT ELEMENT, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS NO TRACE
OF DI-KIRONIUM
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE
OR IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
SUPPOSE IT
CAMOUFLAGED ITSELF?
LET'S ASSUME
THAT IT'S INTELLIGENT,
THAT IT KNOWS THAT
WE'RE LOOKING FOR IT.
TO HIDE FROM A SENSOR SCAN,
IT WOULD HAVE TO
BE ABLE TO CHANGE
ITS MOLECULAR STRUCTURE,
LIKE GOLD
CHANGING ITSELF TO LEAD
OR WOOD CHANGING ITSELF
TO IVORY.
YOU'VE JUST
SUGGESTED SOMETHING...
THAT NEVER OCCURRED
TO ME.
IT MAY PROVIDE SOME
ANSWERS TO A TAPE RECORD
WHICH I THINK
YOU'LL FIND DR. McCOY
IS LOOKING AT
THIS VERY MOMENT.
CHEKOV,
TAKE OVER ON SCANNER.
ENSIGN GARROVICK
REPORTING, SIR.
ARE YOU
THE NEW SECURITY OFFICER?
YES, SIR.
WAS YOUR FATHER--
YES, SIR, HE WAS,
BUT I DON'T EXPECT
ANY SPECIAL TREATMENT
ON THAT ACCOUNT.
YOU'LL GET NONE
ABOARD THIS SHIP, MISTER.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE A REPORT
ON ENSIGN RIZZO.
HE'S DEAD, SIR.
YOU KNEW RIZZO?
YES, SIR.
WE WERE GOOD FRIENDS,
GRADUATED
THE ACADEMY TOGETHER.
YOU'LL GET A CRACK
AT WHAT KILLED HIM.
INTERESTED?
YES, I AM, SIR.
I WANT 4 MEN
ARMED WITH PHASER TWO
SET FOR DISRUPTER EFFECT.
JOIN ME IN THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM IN 5 MINUTES.
YOU'LL ACCOMPANY ME
TO THE PLANET SURFACE.
YES, SIR.
[TRICORDER BEEPING]
READING IS CHANGING, SIR.
SPOCK WAS RIGHT.
NOTICE THE MOLECULAR SHIFT?
DI-KIRONIUM
READING NOW, SIR.
BEARING 94 MARK 7,
ANGLE OF ELEVATION
6 DEGREES, HOLDING STEADY.
OVER THAT RISE.
TAKE TWO MEN,
CIRCLE AROUND
TO THE LEFT.
I'LL TAKE
THE OTHER TWO
AND GO
THE OTHER WAY.
THE CREATURE
IS DANGEROUS.
IF YOU SEE IT...
FIRE FULL PHASERS.
YES, SIR.
HENSON, BARDOLI...
COME WITH ME.
A PHASER!
COME ON!
GARROVICK, DID YOU--
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3619.6.
ONE OF THE MEN IN CRITICAL
CONDITION, THE OTHER IS DEAD.
AND I, I AM NOW
EVEN MORE CONVINCED
THAT THIS IS NOT ONLY
AN INTELLIGENT CREATURE,
BUT THE SAME WHICH
DECIMATED THE CREW
OF THE U.S.S. "FARRAGUT"
11 YEARS AGO IN ANOTHER
PART OF THE GALAXY.
BOTH SPOCK AND McCOY
ARE DOUBTFUL OF THIS,
AND I SENSE THEY ALSO
DOUBT MY DECISION
TO STAY AND FIGHT THE THING.
WHY AM I KEEPING THE SHIP HERE?
MR. GARROVICK, WE'VE
STUDIED YOUR REPORT.
MR. SPOCK, BEGIN.
WHAT WAS THE SIZE
OF THE THING YOU SAW,
ENSIGN?
I'D SAY IT MEASURED
FROM, UH...
10 TO 60 CUBIC METERS,
SIR.
IT VARIED IN SIZE,
FLUCTUATED AS IT MOVED.
COMPOSITION?
IT WAS LIKE A--A...
GASEOUS CLOUD.
PARTS OF IT
I COULD SEE THROUGH.
OTHER PARTS
WERE MORE DENSE.
ENSIGN, DID YOU
SENSE ANY INTELLIGENCE
IN THIS GASEOUS CLOUD?
DID I WHAT, SIR?
DID YOU GET
ANY SUBCONSCIOUS
IMPRESSIONS
THAT THIS WAS A CREATURE,
A LIVING, THINKING THING,
RATHER THAN JUST
A STRANGE CLOUD
OF CHEMICAL ELEMENTS?
NO, SIR.
BUT YOU DIDN'T COME INTO
ACTUAL CONTACT WITH IT,
DID YOU?
NO, SIR. I WAS
FURTHEST AWAY FROM IT.
IT, UH...
IT SEEMED
TO COME OUT OF NOWHERE,
HOVERED FOR A MOMENT,
THEN MOVED TOWARD MY MEN.
IT WAS FAST,
INCREDIBLY FAST.
DID YOU SAY IT HOVERED?
YES, SIR.
YOU DID FIRE AT IT?
YES, SIR, I DID.
WHAT DISTANCE WERE YOU
FROM THE CREATURE?
ABOUT...20 YARDS, SIR.
YOU FIRED AT A LARGE,
HOVERING TARGET
AT THAT DISTANCE
AND MISSED?
YES. I--
WELL, I DIDN'T FIRE
WHILE IT WAS HOVERING, SIR.
YOU MEAN YOU FROZE?
NO...SIR. I...
DIDN'T EXACTLY FREEZE.
WHAT EXACTLY
WERE YOU DOING?
WELL, I WAS STARTLED...
FOR A SECOND.
AND THEN...
BY THE TIME I FIRED,
THE THING WAS
ALREADY MOVING.
DO YOU HAVE ANY
FURTHER INFORMATION?
NO, SIR.
DO YOU GENTLEMEN HAVE
ANY FURTHER QUESTIONS?
I, UH...
I ONLY HESITATED
FOR A MOMENT, SIR.
I'M SORRY.
ENSIGN, YOU'RE RELIEVED
OF ALL DUTIES
AND CONFINED TO QUARTERS
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
YES, SIR.
YOU WERE A LITTLE HARD
ON THE BOY, JIM.
HE FROZE.
ONE MAN WAS KILLED.
ANOTHER MAY DIE.
CAPTAIN,
SCIENTIFICALLY--
YOU'LL BOTH
BE FILING REPORTS.
MAKE YOUR COMMENTS
AND RECOMMENDATIONS THEN.
CAPTAIN,
WHILE WE WAIT,
I'VE TAKEN THE
LIBERTY OF CLEANING
THE RADIOACTIVE
DISPOSAL VENT ON
NUMBER 2 IMPULSE ENGINE,
BUT WE'LL BE READY
TO LEAVE ORBIT
IN UNDER HALF AN HOUR.
WE'RE NOT LEAVING ORBIT,
MR. SCOTT.
NOT THAT QUICKLY.
CAPTAIN, "YORKTOWN" REQUESTING
INFORMATION ON HOW SOON
WE EXPECT TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THEM.
THANK YOU.
THE MEDICINE
FOR THETA 7 COLONY
IS NOT ONLY NEEDED
DESPERATELY, IT HAS
A LIMITED STABILITY--
I'M AWARE
OF THE SITUATION, ENGINEER,
AND I'M GETTING
A LITTLE TIRED
OF MY SENIOR OFFICERS
CONSPIRING AGAINST ME.
FORGIVE ME.
PERHAPS I SHOULDN'T HAVE USED
THE WORD CONSPIRE.
AGREED, SIR.
SCANNER READINGS.
NOTHING, SIR.
CONTINUING TO SCAN.
ARE YOU AWARE THAT
IT CAN CHANGE ITS
MOLECULAR STRUCTURE?
YES, SIR.
ARE YOU SCANNING
FOR ANY UNUSUAL
MOVEMENT?
YES, SIR.
ANY TYPE
OF GASEOUS CLOUD?
WE'VE RUN A FULL
SCANNER PROBE TWICE.
THEN RUN IT 20 TIMES
IF THAT'S
WHAT IT TAKES!
I HOPE I'M NOT
DISTURBING YOU, DOCTOR.
INTERRUPTING
ANOTHER AUTOPSY REPORT
IS NO DISTURBANCE, MR. SPOCK.
IT'S A RELIEF.
I NEED YOUR ADVICE.
THEN I NEED A DRINK.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND
YOUR REASONING.
YOU NEED ADVICE
FROM ME?
YOU MUST BE KIDDING.
I DO NOT JOKE,
DOCTOR.
PERHAPS I
SHOULD REPHRASE
MY STATEMENT.
I REQUIRE
AN OPINION.
THERE ARE MANY ASPECTS
OF HUMAN IRRATIONALITY
I DO NOT YET COMPREHEND...
OBSESSION, FOR ONE.
THE PERSISTENT,
SINGLE-MINDED FIXATION
ON ONE IDEA.
JIM AND HIS CREATURE?
PRECISELY.
HAVE YOU STUDIED
THE INCIDENT
INVOLVING
THE U.S.S. "FARRAGUT"?
NO. WITH ALL THESE
DEATHS AND INJURIES,
I'VE ONLY HAD A CHANCE
TO SCAN THE TAPES.
THERE ARE 8 OR 10 HOURS
OF RECORD TAPES THERE.
FORTUNATELY,
I READ SOMEWHAT FASTER.
IN BRIEF, DOCTOR,
NEARLY HALF THE CREW,
AND THE CAPTAIN,
WERE ANNIHILATED.
THE CAPTAIN'S NAME
WAS GARROVICK.
THE SAME AS OUR ENSIGN.
HIS FATHER.
AMONG THE SURVIVORS
WAS A YOUNG OFFICER
ON HIS FIRST
DEEP-SPACE ASSIGNMENT--
JAMES T. KIRK.
AND THERE IS STILL MORE.
I SUGGEST YOU STUDY THIS.
Kirk, voice-over:
PERSONAL LOG, STARDATE 3620.7.
HAVE I THE RIGHT TO JEOPARDIZE
MY CREW, MY SHIP
FOR A FEELING I CAN'T EVEN
PUT INTO WORDS?
NO MAN ACHIEVES
STARFLEET COMMAND
WITHOUT RELYING ON INTUITION,
BUT HAVE I MADE
A RATIONAL DECISION?
AM I LETTING
THE HORRORS OF THE PAST
DISTORT MY JUDGMENT
OF THE PRESENT?
MIND IF I COME IN?
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
SCANNING REPORT.
Chekov: CONTINUED SCANNING, SIR.
NO UNUSUAL READINGS.
MAINTAIN SEARCH.
KIRK OUT.
IT CAN'T HAVE
JUST VANISHED.
SOMETIMES THEY DO,
IF WE'RE LUCKY.
MONSTERS COME
IN MANY FORMS.
YOU KNOW THE GREATEST
MONSTER OF THEM ALL,
JIM?
GUILT.
GET TO THE POINT.
JIM, WHEN
A YOUNG OFFICER
IS EXPOSED
TO UNKNOWN DANGERS
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
HE'S UNDER TREMENDOUS
EMOTIONAL STRESS.
NOW, WE ALL KNOW THAT.
ENSIGN GARROVICK IS
A SHIP-COMMAND DECISION.
YOU'RE STRAYING OUT OF
YOUR FIELD, DOCTOR.
AM I?
I WAS SPEAKING OF
LIEUTENANT JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
"FARRAGUT."
11 YEARS AGO, YOU
WERE THE YOUNG OFFICER
AT THE PHASER STATION
WHEN SOMETHING ATTACKED.
ACCORDING TO THE TAPES,
THIS YOUNG
LIEUTENANT KIRK
INSISTED
UPON BLAMING HIMSELF.
BECAUSE I DELAYED
IN THE FIRING AT IT.
YOU HAD
A NORMAL EMOTION.
YOU WERE STARTLED.
YOU DELAYED FIRING
FOR A GRAND TOTAL
OF PERHAPS TWO SECONDS.
IF I HADN'T DELAYED,
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED.
THE SHIP'S EXEC
DIDN'T SEEM TO THINK SO.
HIS LOG ENTRY
WAS QUITE CLEAR
ON THE SUBJECT--
"LIEUTENANT KIRK
IS A FINE YOUNG OFFICER
WHO PERFORMED
WITH UNCOMMON BRAVERY."
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT KILLED 200 CREWMEN.
CAPTAIN GARROVICK WAS
VERY IMPORTANT TO YOU,
WASN'T HE, JIM?
YES.
HE WAS
MY COMMANDING OFFICER
FROM THE DAY
I LEFT THE ACADEMY.
ONE OF THE FINEST MEN
I EVER KNEW.
I COULD HAVE KILLED
THAT THING
IF I'D FIRED SOON ENOUGH
THE FIRST TIME.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT, JIM.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT
ANY MORE THAN YOU
KNOW THAT GARROVICK
COULD HAVE DESTROYED IT.
I CAN'T HELP HOW I FEEL.
THERE'S...
AN INTELLIGENCE
ABOUT IT, BONES.
A MALEVOLENCE. IT'S EVIL.
IT MUST BE DESTROYED.
TO BE SO OBSESSED...
OBSESSED?
THAT YOU
COULD DESTROY YOURSELF,
YOUR CAREER, A YOUNG BOY
WHO REMINDS YOU OF
YOURSELF 11 YEARS AGO.
DON'T PUSH OUR FRIENDSHIP
PAST THE POINT
WHERE I HAVE TO TAKE
OFFICIAL--
I'M NOT, JIM.
THIS IS PROFESSIONAL,
CAPTAIN.
I AM PREPARING
A MEDICAL LOG ENTRY
ON MY ESTIMATION
OF THE PHYSICAL
AND EMOTIONAL CONDITION
OF A STARSHIP CAPTAIN.
WHICH REQUIRES A WITNESS
OF COMMAND GRADE.
DO I TAKE IT, DOCTOR,
COMMANDER...
THAT BOTH OF YOU
OR EITHER OF YOU
CONSIDER ME UNFIT
OR INCAPACITATED?
CORRECTLY PHRASED,
CAPTAIN.
AS RECOMMENDED
IN THE MANUAL.
OUR REPLY,
ALSO AS RECOMMENDED, IS,
SIR, WE HAVE NOTED
IN YOUR RECENT BEHAVIOR
CERTAIN ITEMS,
WHICH, ON THE SURFACE,
SEEM UNUSUAL.
WE RESPECTFULLY
ASK PERMISSION
TO INQUIRE FURTHER--
BLAST IT!
FORGET THE MANUAL!
ASK YOUR QUESTIONS.
SIR, THE U.S.S. "YORKTOWN"
IS WAITING NOW
AT THE RENDEZVOUS POINT.
IT CARRIES
PERISHABLE DRUGS--
SPARE ME THE RECITATION,
SPOCK. I KNOW THE FACTS.
THEY NEED
THOSE VACCINES ON
THETA 7, CAPTAIN.
NOW, WHY ARE WE
DELAYING HERE?
BECAUSE I'M CONVINCED THAT
THIS IS THE SAME CREATURE
THAT ATTACKED THE "FARRAGUT"
11 YEARS AGO.
CREATURE, CAPTAIN?
MY REPORT IS ON THE TAPES.
AS IT ATTACKED US
11 YEARS AGO,
AS I LOST CONSCIOUSNESS,
I COULD FEEL
THE INTELLIGENCE OF THE THING.
I COULD SENSE IT
THINKING, PLANNING.
YOU SAY YOU COULD SENSE
ITS INTELLIGENCE, CAPTAIN?
HOW DID IT
COMMUNICATE WITH YOU?
YOU STATE
THAT IT HAPPENED
JUST AS YOU LOST
CONSCIOUSNESS.
A SEMICONSCIOUS MIND
IS A VERY
TRICKY THING.
A MAN NEVER KNOWS
JUST HOW MUCH
IS REAL
OR HOW MUCH
IS IMAGINATION.
WHATEVER IT IS, DOCTOR,
WHATEVER IT IS,
WOULDN'T YOU CALL IT DEADLY?
YES. THERE'S
NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
AND WHAT IF IT IS
THE SAME CREATURE
THAT ATTACKED 11 YEARS AGO,
FROM A PLANET OVER
1,000 LIGHT-YEARS FROM HERE?
OBVIOUSLY, CAPTAIN, IF IT IS
AN INTELLIGENT CREATURE,
IF IT IS THE SAME ONE,
IF IT THEREFORE IS
CAPABLE OF SPACE TRAVEL,
IT COULD POSE A GREAT THREAT
TO INHABITED PLANETS.
A LOT OF IFS, I AGREE,
BUT IN
MY COMMAND JUDGMENT,
THEY OUTWEIGH
OTHER FACTORS.
INTUITION, HOWEVER
ILLOGICAL, MR. SPOCK,
IS RECOGNIZED
AS A COMMAND PREROGATIVE.
JIM, WE'RE NOT TRYING
TO GANG UP ON YOU.
AND YOU HAVEN'T, DOCTOR.
YOU'VE EXPRESSED
THE PROPER CONCERN,
YOU'VE ASKED
THE PROPER QUESTIONS.
YOU'VE BOTH
DONE YOUR DUTY.
NOW, MAY I ASK
WHAT MEDICAL LOG ENTRY
YOU INTEND TO MAKE?
AT THIS POINT,
MY MEDICAL LOG
REMAINS OPEN.
IN THAT CASE, GENTLEMEN--
Chekov:
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN.
COME IN.
KIRK HERE.
I HAVE A READING
ON THE, UH,
WHATEVER IT IS,
CAPTAIN,
LEAVING
THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
HEADING INTO SPACE.
ALL DECKS, RED ALERT.
RED ALERT.
PREPARE TO LEAVE ORBIT.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
CAPTAIN, WE CAN'T MAINTAIN
WARP 8 SPEED MUCH LONGER.
PRESSURES ARE APPROACHING
THE CRITICAL POINT.
RANGE, MR. CHEKOV.
.04 LIGHT-YEARS AHEAD.
OUR PHASERS WON'T
REACH IT, SIR.
WE ARE BARELY CLOSING IN
ON IT, CAPTAIN.
WE COULD BE
PURSUING IT FOR DAYS.
IF NECESSARY.
DO WHAT YOU CAN TO
INCREASE OUR SPEED, SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
EXTREME MAGNIFICATION,
MR. CHEKOV.
MAGNIFICATION...12.
THERE, SIR...
GOT IT.
SPOCK...
HOW DO YOU READ THAT?
CONFLICTING DATA, CAPTAIN.
IT SEEMS TO BE
IN A BORDERLINE STATE
BETWEEN MATTER AND ENERGY--
ELEMENTS OF BOTH.
IT COULD POSSIBLY USE
GRAVITATIONAL FIELDS
FOR PROPULSION.
AND YOU DON'T FIND THAT
SOPHISTICATED, MR. SPOCK?
EXTREMELY EFFICIENT,
CAPTAIN.
WHETHER THAT INDICATES
INTELLIGENCE
IS ANOTHER MATTER.
OPEN HATCH ON IMPULSE
ENGINE NUMBER 2.
MR. SCOTT WAS DOING
AN A.I.D. CLEANUP ON IT.
WE WON'T BE USING
THE IMPULSE ENGINES.
TURN THE ALARM OFF.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, WE CAN'T DO IT.
IF WE KEEP THIS SPEED,
WE'LL BLOW UP
ANY MINUTE NOW.
GO TO WARP 6.
HI.
EVERYONE ELSE
IS AT ALERT STATION,
SO I BROUGHT YOU
SOME DINNER.
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
ARE WE STILL
CHASING THAT THING
HALFWAY ACROSS THE GALAXY?
YES.
HAS THE CAPTAIN LOST
HIS SENSE OF BALANCE?
MAYBE.
IS THE ENTIRE CREW
ABOUT READY TO EXPLODE?
POSITIVELY.
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU'RE OUT OF IT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
OUT OF IT?
I CAUSED IT.
YOU KNOW THAT, TOO,
DON'T YOU?
IF I'D FIRED MY PHASER
QUICKLY ENOUGH
ON ARGUS 10,
THIS WOULDN'T HAVE
HAPPENED.
YOU KNOW, SELF-PITY'S
A TERRIBLE FIRST COURSE.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
THE SOUP INSTEAD?
I TOLD YOU, CHRISTINE,
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
DR. McCOY THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
SAY SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THIS IS HIS OFFICIALLY LOGGED
PRESCRIPTION FOR YOU.
IT HAS ONE WORD ON IT--
EAT.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T
FOLLOW HIS ORDERS,
DR. McCOY COULD
AND POSSIBLY WOULD
HAVE YOU HAULED DOWN
TO SICKBAY
AND FED INTRAVENOUSLY.
WHAT'S THAT?
HMM? THIS?
A SURVEY ON CYGNIAN
RESPIRATORY DISEASES?
I THOUGHT YOU TOOK
GARROVICK SOME FOOD.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
WITH THIS?
APPLYING PSYCHOLOGY.
THE CREATURE IS SLOWING.
IT'S DOWN TO WARP 2.
REDUCE SPEED.
APPROACH SLOWLY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
IT WAS
OUTRUNNING US.
MAYBE IT'S DECIDED
TO FIGHT.
PHASERS READY.
PHASERS
SHOW READY, SIR.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
Kirk: BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL DECKS TO BATTLE STATIONS.
THIS IS NOT A DRILL.
ALL DECKS
TO BATTLE STATIONS.
IT'S COMING
TO A FULL HALT, SIR.
MAGNIFICATION 1.
MOVE IN CLOSELY,
MR. CHEKOV.
SUBLIGHT ONE-QUARTER SPEED.
CAPTAIN, REQUEST PERMISSION
TO RETURN TO MY POST.
WITHIN PHASER RANGE,
SIR.
LOCK ALL PHASERS
ON TARGET.
LOCKED ON TARGET.
FIRE PHASERS,
MR. CHEKOV.
PHASERS INEFFECTUAL,
SIR.
PHOTON TORPEDOES.
MINIMUM SPREAD PATTERN.
MINIMUM PATTERN
READY, SIR.
FIRE PHOTON TORPEDOES.
THERE.
IT'S COMING, SIR.
DEFLECTORS UP.
DEFLECTORS UP, SIR.
THE DEFLECTORS
WILL NOT STOP IT,
CAPTAIN.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WE SHOULD
HAVE SURMISED THIS.
FOR THE CREATURE
TO BE ABLE TO USE GRAVITY
AS A PROPULSIVE FORCE,
IT WOULD HAVE TO HAVE
THIS CAPACITY.
5 SECONDS TO CONTACT.
ALL HATCHES
AND VENTS SECURE.
ALL LIGHTS ON THE BOARD
SHOW GREEN.
SIR! THE NUMBER 2
IMPULSE VENT--
WE HAVE A RED LIGHT.
CAPTAIN,
SOMETHING'S ENTERED
THROUGH THE NUMBER 2
IMPULSE VENT.
NEGATIVE PRESSURE
IN ALL SHIP'S VENTS.
ALERT ALL DECKS.
[BEEPING]
REPORT.
WHEN IT ENTERED
IMPULSE ENGINE
NUMBER 2's VENT,
IT ATTACKED 2 CREWMEN,
THEN GOT INTO THE
VENTILATING SYSTEM,
AND NOW WE HAVE AIR
FOR ONLY 2 HOURS.
BONES.
ONE MAN HAS A CHANCE
FOR SURVIVAL.
THE OTHER IS DEAD.
YOU CAN ADD THAT LITTLE
PRICE TAG TO YOUR MONSTER HUNT.
THAT'S ENOUGH, BONES.
IT'S NOT ENOUGH!
YOU DIDN'T CARE
WHAT HAPPENED
AS LONG AS YOU COULD
HANG YOUR TROPHY ON THE WALL.
WELL, IT'S NOT ON IT,
CAPTAIN, IT'S IN IT.
GENTLEMEN, MAY I SUGGEST
THAT WE NO LONGER
BELABOR THE QUESTION
OF WHETHER OR NOT
WE SHOULD HAVE GONE
AFTER THE CREATURE?
THE MATTER HAS BEEN
RENDERED ACADEMIC.
THE CREATURE IS NOW
AFTER US.
CREATURE, MR. SPOCK?
IT TURNED AND ATTACKED,
DOCTOR.
ITS METHOD
WAS WELL-CONSIDERED
AND INTELLIGENT.
YES, WELL,
IT COULD HAVE BEEN
MANY LIGHT-YEARS
AWAY FROM US.
INSTEAD IT CHOSE
TO TURN AND ATTACK
HERE. WHY?
IMPOSSIBLE TO TELL,
CAPTAIN,
UNTIL I CAN MAKE
A CLOSER SURVEY
OF THE CREATURE.
SCOTTY, TRY FLUSHING
THE RADIOACTIVE WASTE INTO
THE VENTILATION SYSTEM.
SEE WHAT EFFECT
THAT HAS.
AYE.
I'M SORRY, JIM.
I WAS WRONG.
CAPTAIN.
THE CREATURE'S ABILITY
TO THROW ITSELF
OUT OF TIME SYNC
MAKES IT POSSIBLE
FOR IT TO BE ELSEWHERE
IN THE INSTANT
THE PHASER HITS.
THERE IS THEREFORE NO BASIS
FOR YOUR SELF-RECRIMINATION.
IF YOU HAD FIRED, ON TIME
AND ON TARGET, 11 YEARS AGO,
IT WOULD HAVE MADE
NO MORE DIFFERENCE
THAN IT DID AN HOUR AGO.
CAPTAIN GARROVICK
WOULD STILL BE DEAD.
THE FAULT
WAS NOT YOURS, JIM.
IN FACT,
THERE WAS NO FAULT.
IF YOU WANT TO PLAY
ANALYST, SPOCK,
USE SOMEONE ELSE,
NOT ME.
MY CONCERN
IS WITH THE SHIP
AND THE CREW.
[BUZZER]
COME IN.
ENSIGN, AM I CORRECT
IN MY ASSUMPTION
THAT YOU'VE
BEEN DISTURBED
BY WHAT YOU CONSIDER
TO BE
A FAILURE
ON YOUR PART?
I WOULD LIKE YOU
TO CONSIDER
THAT THE HESITATION
FOR WHICH YOU ARE
BLAMING YOURSELF
IS AN HEREDITARY TRAIT
OF YOUR SPECIES.
WHEN SUDDENLY FACED
BY THE UNKNOWN
OR IMMINENT DANGER,
A HUMAN WILL INVARIABLY
EXPERIENCE
A SPLIT SECOND
OF INDECISION.
HE HESITATES.
DO I HAVE
YOUR ATTENTION, ENSIGN?
YES, SIR.
I KNOW YOU WOULD PREFER
TO WALLOW
IN A POOL OF EMOTION
RATHER THAN--
MR. SPOCK...
IT'S VERY KIND OF YOU
TO COME HERE--
KINDNESS, MR. GARROVICK,
IS ANOTHER HUMAN EMOTION,
AND I BELIEVE
WE HAVE ENOUGH OF THAT.
I SIMPLY WOULD LIKE YOU
TO ACCEPT THE FACT
THAT YOUR REACTION
HAS ITS BASIS IN PHYSIO--
DO YOU SMELL SOMETHING?
SIR, IT'S COMING
THROUGH THE VENT.
GET OUT OF HERE!
I'LL ATTEMPT TO
SEAL IT OFF.
SIR, THE CREATURE'S
IN MY CABIN.
IT'S GOT MR. SPOCK.
ON MY WAY, GARROVICK.
SECURITY TO 341.
MEDICAL ALERT.
SCOTTY, REVERSE
CABIN PRESSURE 341.
SECURITY, HOLD IT.
TRICORDER.
JIM, SPOCK
MAY BE DYING.
IF WE LET THAT THING
INTO THE SHIP,
HE'LL HAVE A LOT
OF COMPANY.
I MUST HAVE JAMMED
THE VENT CONTROL
WHEN I HIT IT.
SEE IF
THE REVERSE PRESSURE
HAS PULLED IT BACK INTO
THE VENTILATION SYSTEM.
HE SAVED MY LIFE,
CAPTAIN.
I SHOULD BE LYING DEAD
IN THERE, NOT HIM.
FORTUNATELY,
NEITHER OF US
IS DEAD, ENSIGN.
THE REVERSE
PRESSURE WORKED.
THE VENT IS CLOSED.
DON'T MISUNDERSTAND
MY NEXT QUESTION.
MR. SPOCK,
WHY AREN'T YOU DEAD?
IT'S THAT GREEN
BLOOD OF HIS.
My hemoglobin
is based on copper,
not iron.
I'LL BET HE LEFT
A BAD TASTE
IN THE
CREATURE'S
MOUTH, TOO.
COLLOQUIALLY EXPRESSED,
BUT ESSENTIALLY CORRECT.
YEAH.
[SNIFFS]
THE SCENT IS DIFFERENT.
I THINK I UNDERSTAND
SOMETHING NOW.
DO YOU BELIEVE
YOU'RE IN COMMUNICATION
WITH THE CREATURE,
CAPTAIN?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT IS, MR. SPOCK,
BUT DO YOU REMEMBER I SAID
THE THING WAS ALIVE?
IT MAY NOT BE COMMUNICATION
AS WE UNDERSTAND IT,
BUT I DID KNOW
IT WAS ALIVE AND INTELLIGENT,
AND I THINK I KNOW
SOMETHING ELSE NOW.
[INTERCOM SIGNAL]
Scotty:
ENGINEERING
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
SCOTT, CAPTAIN.
THE CREATURE'S
MOVING BACK
TOWARD THE NUMBER 2
IMPULSE VENT.
THE RADIOACTIVE FLUSHING
MAY BE AFFECTING IT.
OPEN THE VENT.
ON MY WAY TO THE BRIDGE.
KIRK OUT.
ENSIGN GARROVICK.
YES, SIR.
YOU WERE ON THE BRIDGE
WHEN WE WERE ATTACKED.
YES, I'M SORRY, SIR.
I KNOW I WAS CONFINED
TO QUARTERS, BUT WHEN
THE ALERT SOUNDED--
VERY COMMENDABLE, ENSIGN.
WHAT WAS YOUR IMPRESSION
OF THE BATTLE?
I DON'T
UNDERSTAND, SIR.
I'M ASKING FOR
YOUR MILITARY APPRAISAL
OF THE TECHNIQUES
USED AGAINST THE CREATURE.
INEFFECTIVE, CAPTAIN.
I REALIZE, CAPTAIN,
YOU DID EVERYTHING
YOU COULD DO.
I KNOW THAT.
IT'S JUST
THAT NOTHING WORKS
AGAINST A MONSTER
THAT CAN DO THE THINGS
THAT THING DOES.
AND, ENSIGN,
WHAT IS YOUR APPRAISAL
OF YOUR CONDUCT
ON THE PLANET?
I DELAYED FIRING.
AND IF YOU HADN'T
DELAYED FIRING...
MM.
NO DIFFERENCE, ENSIGN.
NO WEAPON KNOWN
WOULD HAVE MADE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
THEN...
OR 11 YEARS AGO.
REPORT FOR DUTY, ENSIGN.
YES, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU, SIR!
REPORT,
MR. CHEKOV.
RESULTS POSITIVE,
CAPTAIN.
THE CREATURE
HAS LEFT THE SHIP
AT HIGH WARP SPEED
AND IS ALREADY NEARLY
OUT OF SCANNER RANGE.
THE WAY THAT THING
CAN MOVE, CAPTAIN,
I WOULDN'T BELIEVE.
DIRECTION,
MR. SPOCK.
IT WAS BEARING 127,
MARK 9,
BUT I'VE LOST IT NOW.
MR. SCOTT,
I'LL NEED ALL THE SPEED
YOU CAN DELIVER.
KEEP AT IT UNTIL WE
BEGIN TO SHAKE APART.
KIRK OUT.
I BELIEVE I KNOW
WHERE IT'S GOING.
IT HAS CHANGED COURSE BEFORE
TO MISLEAD US, CAPTAIN.
LOGIC WOULD DICTATE--
NO. I'M PLAYING
INTUITION.
MR. CHEKOV, COMPUTE
A COURSE FOR TYCHOS
STAR SYSTEM.
COMPUTED AND ON THE BOARD, SIR.
AHEAD FULL.
AHEAD FULL, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTACT STARFLEET
AND THE U.S.S.
"YORKTOWN."
FREQUENCY
OPEN AND CLEAR, SIR.
INFORM THEM
THAT WE ARE PURSUING
THE CREATURE
TO PLANET 4
OF THAT SYSTEM.
THAT'S THE LOCATION
OF ITS ATTACK
ON THE U.S.S "FARRAGUT"
11 YEARS AGO.
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
IN GARROVICK'S QUARTERS,
I SAID THE SCENT
OF THE CREATURE
WAS SOMEHOW DIFFERENT.
SOMETHING IN MY MIND
SAID "HOME."
AND YOU KNOW
WHERE HOME IS, CAPTAIN?
YES, I THINK I DO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW I KNOW,
BUT HOME...
IS WHERE
IT FOUGHT A STARSHIP
ONCE BEFORE.
GIVE THEM
OUR TACTICAL SITUATION
AND INFORM THEM
I'M COMMITTING THIS VESSEL
TO THE DESTRUCTION
OF THE CREATURE.
WE WILL RENDEZVOUS--
ROUND-TRIP TIME,
MR. CHEKOV.
1.7 DAYS, SIR.
WE WILL RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE U.S.S. "YORKTOWN"...
IN 48 HOURS.
I ASSUME
THAT YOU NOW BELIEVE
WE SHOULD PURSUE
THE CREATURE
AND DESTROY IT.
PRECISELY.
YOU DON'T AGREE
WITH MR. SPOCK?
IT'S THE TIME FACTOR
THAT BOTHERS ME.
THOSE DRUGS ARE PERISHABLE.
DOCTOR,
EVIDENCE INDICATES
THE CREATURE IS HERE
TO SPAWN.
IF SO, IT WILL REPRODUCE
BY FISSION,
NOT JUST INTO TWO PARTS,
BUT THOUSANDS.
ANTIMATTER SEEMS
OUR ONLY POSSIBILITY.
AN OUNCE SHOULD
BE SUFFICIENT.
WE CAN DRAIN IT
FROM THE SHIP'S ENGINES,
TRANSPORT IT
TO THE PLANET'S SURFACE
IN A MAGNETIC
VACUUM FIELD.
CONTACT MEDICAL STORES.
I WANT AS MUCH HEMOPLASM
AS THEY CAN SPARE
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
IN 15 MINUTES.
YES, SIR.
I PRESUME YOU INTEND TO USE
THAT HEMOPLASM
TO ATTRACT THE CREATURE?
WE MUST GET IT
TO THE ANTIMATTER.
IT SEEMS ATTRACTED
TO RED BLOOD CELLS.
WHAT BETTER BAIT
COULD WE HAVE?
THERE IS STILL
ONE PROBLEM, CAPTAIN.
THE BLAST, YES.
EXACTLY.
A MATTER/ANTIMATTER BLAST
WILL RIP AWAY
HALF THE PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE.
IF OUR VESSEL IS IN ORBIT
AND ENCOUNTERS
THOSE SHOCK WAVES--
A CHANCE WE'LL
HAVE TO TAKE, MR. SPOCK.
ALSO, WE CANNOT BE CERTAIN
THE TRANSPORTER WILL OPERATE
UNDER THOSE CONDITIONS.
IF A MAN IS BEAMING UP
WHEN THAT HITS,
WE MAY LOSE HIM.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
I'VE DECIDED
TO SET THE TRAP MYSELF.
CAPTAIN, THERE IS SO LITTLE
HEMOGLOBIN IN MY GREEN BLOOD,
THE CREATURE COULD NOT
HARM ME EXTENSIVELY.
IT THEREFORE SEEMS LOGICAL
FOR ME TO BE THE ONE--
NEGATIVE, MR. SPOCK.
IN CASE THIS PLAN FAILS,
I'LL NEED YOU ABOARD
THE SHIP.
IN THAT EVENT,
WE'LL NEED ANOTHER PLAN.
IT WILL REQUIRE TWO MEN
TO TRANSPORT
THE ANTIMATTER UNIT.
I'D LIKE PERMISSION
TO GO WITH YOU, SIR.
I HAD YOU IN MIND,
MR. GARROVICK.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
PROCEED IMMEDIATELY
TO MAXIMUM ORBIT.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
JUST THINK, CAPTAIN,
LESS THAN ONE OUNCE
OF ANTIMATTER HERE
IS MORE POWERFUL
THAN 10,000
COBALT BOMBS.
LET'S HOPE IT'S AS POWERFUL
AS MAN WILL EVER GET.
DETONATOR.
AYE, SIR.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
HOLDING AT 30,000
KILOMETERS.
ANTIMATTER CONTAINER
POSITIONED AND ARMED.
I'LL CALL YOU BACK
WHEN IT'S BAITED. KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, LOOK!
THE HEMOPLASM.
THE BAIT'S
ALREADY TAKEN.
WE'LL HAVE TO USE
SOMETHING ELSE FOR BAIT.
SIR, THAT THING
ONLY FEEDS ON BLOOD.
GARROVICK,
GET BACK TO THE SHIP.
TELL THEM TO PREPARE
TO DETONATE.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO BE THE BAIT.
I SAID GET BACK TO THE SHIP.
ENSIGN,
I GAVE YOU AN ORDER.
YES, SIR.
CONSIDER YOURSELF
ON REPORT.
THIS IS NO TIME
FOR HEROICS.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF SACRIFICING MYSELF,
AT LEAST NOT YET.
SPOCK...SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
SCAN US...
AND LOCK ONTO US.
IT'S GOING TO BE CLOSE.
VERY, VERY CLOSE.
STAND BY.
STAND BY, "ENTERPRISE."
I CAN SMELL IT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S SICKENING.
HONEY SWEET.
STAND BY, "ENTERPRISE."
NOW!
ENERGIZE
AND DETONATE.
RESET.
ENERGIZE.
Chekov: ALL DECKS STAND BY.
SHOCK WAVES.
DO SOMETHING.
WE ARE, DOCTOR.
CROSS-CIRCUITING TO "A."
GOT THEM.
A PIECE OF THEM, ANYWAY.
CROSS-CIRCUITING TO "B."
CRAZY WAY TO TRAVEL,
SPREADING
A MAN'S MOLECULES
ALL OVER THE UNIVERSE.
CAPTAIN...
THANK HEAVEN.
MR. SCOTT, THERE WAS
NO DEITY INVOLVED.
IT WAS MY CROSS-CIRCUITING
TO "B" THAT RECOVERED THEM.
WELL, THEN,
THANK PITCHFORKS
AND POINTED EARS.
AS LONG
AS IT WORKED, JIM.
THAT'S A FAIR STATEMENT,
BONES.
NOW THAT
THE CREATURE IS DEAD,
LET'S SAVE SOME LIVES.
WE'LL DELIVER
YOUR MEDICINE.
BRIDGE, THIS IS KIRK.
UHURA HERE.
HAVE MR. CHEKOV
LAY IN A COURSE
FOR A RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE "YORKTOWN."
MAXIMUM WARP.
AYE, SIR.
OH, ENSIGN,
MEET ME IN MY QUARTERS
WHEN YOU'VE CLEANED UP.
I'D LIKE TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
SEVERAL...
TALL STORIES I THINK
YOU'D LIKE TO HEAR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I WOULD.