[EXOTIC MUSIC PLAYING]
CAPTAIN, I THINK I'M
GOING TO LIKE ARGELIUS.
OBVIOUSLY A MAN
OF GOOD TASTE.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME
THAT ALL THESE WOMEN--
WELL, THAT ALL THIS IS--
YES, YES, YES.
MM-HMM.
THE ARGELIANS
THINK VERY HIGHLY
OF THEIR PLEASURE.
WELL, NOW, THAT'S
AN UNDERSTATEMENT
IF I EVER HEARD ONE.
THIS IS A COMPLETELY
HEDONISTIC SOCIETY.
YOU LIKE HER, SCOTTY?
AYE.
WHY SHOULDN'T I?
GOOD. I'VE INVITED
HER TO JOIN US
AT THE TABLE.
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
LIKE TO MEET HER.
NOW, THAT'S WHAT I CALL
A REAL CAPTAIN--
ALWAYS THINKING
OF HIS MEN.
[BANGING]
SCOTTY,
SCOTTY, IN ARGELIUS
THEY USE THE LIGHTS.
NOW, NO ONE HAS TO TELL
AN OLD ABERDEEN PUB-CRAWLER
HOW TO APPLAUD, CAPTAIN.
Kirk:
HAVE ONE OF OUR PILLOWS?
'TIS A FINE FOGGY NIGHT
TONIGHT, AND I DOUBT
IF ANYONE HAS EVER TOLD
YOU OF THE MARVELOUS
FOGS WE HAVE
IN ABERDEEN.
Woman: NEVER A WORD,
BUT I'M DYING
TO LEARN.
WELL, THEN, WHY
DON'T I SHOW YOU?
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
A WALK IN THE FOG
WITH A BONNY LASS.
OR A...HANDSOME GENTLEMAN.
Woman: WHY DON'T WE?
YOU DON'T MIND,
DO YOU?
I MIGHT EVEN GET
BACK TO THE SHIP
ON TIME.
WE WON'T LEAVE
WITHOUT YOU,
SCOTTY.
RELAX AND ENJOY
YOURSELF.
MY WORK
IS NEVER DONE.
McCoy: MY WORK, JIM.
THIS IS PRESCRIPTION STUFF.
DON'T FORGET,
THE EXPLOSION
THAT THREW SCOTTY
AGAINST A BULKHEAD WAS
CAUSED BY A WOMAN.
PHYSICALLY
HE'S ALL RIGHT.
AM I RIGHT
IN ASSUMING THAT?
OH, YES, YES
AND, MATTER OF FACT,
CONSIDERABLE
PSYCHOLOGICAL DAMAGE
COULD HAVE BEEN CAUSED--
FOR EXAMPLE, HIS TOTAL
RESENTMENT TOWARD WOMEN.
HE SEEMS
TO BE OVERCOMING
HIS RESENTMENT.
OF COURSE, IN MY
PROFESSIONAL OPINION, WHEN
HE GETS BACK TO THE SHIP,
HE'S GOING TO HATE YOU FOR
MAKING HIM LEAVE ARGELIUS,
BUT THEN, HE WILL HAVE
LOST TOTAL RESENTMENT
TOWARD WOMEN.
MISSION ACCOMPLISHED
AS FAR AS SCOTTY
IS CONCERNED.
BONES...
HMM?
I KNOW
A LITTLE PLACE
ACROSS TOWN
WHERE THE WOMEN--
OH, YES, I KNOW THE PLACE.
I KNOW THE PLACE.
LET'S GO.
I THINK IT'S THAT WAY.
I THINK IT'S
THAT WAY, TOO.
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
SHE'S DEAD, JIM.
STABBED A DOZEN TIMES.
[MOANING]
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE, NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: "CAPTAIN'S LOG,
"STARDATE 3614.9.
"PLANET ARGELIUS II.
"WHILE ON THERAPEUTIC
SHORE LEAVE,
"MR. SCOTT HAS
FALLEN UNDER SUSPICION
"OF HAVING BRUTALLY MURDERED
AN ARGELIAN WOMAN.
"THE CHIEF CITY ADMINISTRATOR,
A MR. HENGIST,
"HAS TAKEN CHARGE
OF THE INVESTIGATION,
BUT HAS LEARNED
LITTLE OF VALUE."
Hengist: I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY, GENTLEMEN.
ARGELIUS IS THE LAST PLANET
IN THE GALAXY I'D EXPECT
A THING LIKE THIS TO HAPPEN.
WE'RE JUST
AS SHOCKED AS YOU
ARE, MR. HENGIST.
IF THIS WAS
MY HOME PLANET, RIGEL IV,
I'D HAVE A DOZEN
INVESTIGATORS WORKING
ON THE MATTER,
BUT THEY DON'T
EXIST HERE.
YOU'RE NOT A NATIVE
OF ARGELIUS, SIR?
OH, NO, NO. ARGELIUS HIRES
ITS ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICERS
FROM OTHER PLANETS. HEH!
THE ARGELIANS AREN'T
VERY EFFICIENT, YOU KNOW,
A GENTLE, HARMLESS PEOPLE.
UH, MR. SCOTT.
NOW, UH, ARE YOU SURE
YOU'VE NEVER
SEEN THIS BEFORE?
I--I DON'T REMEMBER.
Hengist: REALLY, SIR,
THAT IS HARDLY HELPFUL.
SCOTTY...
YOU LEFT THE CAFE
WITH THE GIRL.
DO YOU
REMEMBER THAT?
WHAT
HAPPENED NEXT?
[SIGHS]
WELL, WE WERE...
WALKING IN...THE FOG.
UH, I WAS UP AHEAD
TRYING TO LEAD THE WAY.
I HEARD THE GIRL SCREAM.
I REMEMBER
STARTING TO TURN.
I DON'T REMEMBER
ANOTHER THING.
SCOTTY,
YOU'VE GOT
TO REMEMBER.
JIM.
IF HE SAYS
HE CAN'T REMEMBER,
HE PROBABLY DOESN'T.
YOU KNOW SCOTTY.
I KNOW THAT A MURDER
HAS BEEN COMMITTED.
YOU DON'T THINK,
BY ANY CHANCE,
THAT SCOTTY WAS--
IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE
WHAT I THINK.
BUT YOU DON'T
JUST THROW HIM
TO THE WOLVES.
BONES, I HAVE
A DIPLOMATIC
RESPONSIBILITY.
THIS HAPPENED UNDER
ARGELIAN JURISDICTION.
IF THEY WANT TO
ARREST HIM, TRY HIM,
EVEN CONVICT HIM,
I HAVE TO GO ALONG
WITH IT.
BUT HE'S SUFFERING
FROM A SEVERE
CONCUSSION.
WE'LL DO WHAT WE CAN.
IT'S NOT PROMISING,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SCOTT INSISTS
HE REMEMBERS NOTHING,
BUT MY DETECTOR
READINGS INDICATE
THAT ONLY HIS FINGERPRINTS
ARE ON THE MURDER WEAPON.
YES, MR. HENGIST,
THERE WERE
OTHER PEOPLE
IN THE CAFE
ABOUT THE TIME
OF THE MURDER.
SEVERAL OF THEM LEFT
JUST BEFORE MR. SCOTT
AND THE GIRL DID.
UH, SO I'VE BEEN
INFORMED BY THE STAFF.
THEY'RE BEING LOCATED,
AND WE WILL QUESTION THEM,
BUT, UH, THE OUTLOOK FOR
YOUR FRIEND IS QUITE GRIM.
WHAT IS THE LAW
IN THESE CASES?
Man: THE LAW OF ARGELIUS
IS LOVE.
GENTLEMEN,
OUR PREFECT, JARIS.
SIR, UH, CAPTAIN KIRK
AND DR. McCOY.
AND THIS IS
MY WIFE, SYBO.
AND, UH, THIS MAN
IS SCOTT,
THE ONE I SENT YOU
THE MESSAGE ABOUT.
HMM. HE DOES NOT
LOOK LIKE A MAN
CAPABLE
OF SUCH AN ACT.
STILL,
IT'S BEEN SO LONG.
GENTLEMEN, BEFORE
OUR GREAT AWAKENING
200 YEARS AGO,
WE HAD WAYS OF
LEARNING THE TRUTH
IN SUCH MATTERS.
WE SHALL RETURN
TO THEM.
THE ARGELIAN
EMPATHIC CONTACT?
YOU KNOW OF THIS?
YES, WE'VE HEARD
OF IT.
I ASSUMED IT WAS
A LOST ART.
MY WIFE IS A DESCENDANT
OF THE ANCIENT PRIESTESSES
OF OUR LAND.
SHE HAS
THE ANCESTRAL GIFT.
GENTLEMEN, I HAVE COME
TO INVITE YOU TO MY HOME.
UH, PREFECT, UH, DON'T YOU
THINK THIS SHOULD BE HANDLED
IN AN OFFICIAL MANNER, UH,
THROUGH MY OFFICE?
IT SHALL BE HANDLED
IN AN OFFICIAL MANNER,
MR. HENGIST,
SINCE I AM
THE HIGHEST OFFICIAL.
GENTLEMEN, LET US
PROCEED TO MY HOME,
WHERE, WITH THE AID
OF MY WIFE,
WE SHALL LEARN THE TRUTH.
PLEASE.
DEPENDING ON YOUR WIFE'S
EMPATHIC ABILITIES
IS ALL VERY WELL,
PREFECT,
BUT THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
WE CAN FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS MR. SCOTT
CANNOT REMEMBER.
SINCE YOU FIND IT
IMPOSSIBLE TO LET US
GO BACK UP TO OUR SHIP,
I CAN BEAM DOWN
A TECHNICIAN
WITH A PSYCHO-TRICORDER.
McCoy: UH, PREFECT,
IT WILL GIVE US
A DETAILED ACCOUNT
OF EVERYTHING THAT'S
HAPPENED TO MR. SCOTT
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS.
Hengist:
OH, I-I'D ADVISE
AGAINST IT, PREFECT.
THIS IS PURELY
AN ARGELIAN MATTER.
Prefect:
MY WIFE MUST MEDITATE
FOR A TIME
BEFORE SHE'S READY.
I SEE NO REASON WHY
WE SHOULD NOT USE
THAT TIME
TO GOOD ADVANTAGE.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
"ENTERPRISE."
SPOCK HERE.
MR. SPOCK,
BEAM DOWN A TECHNICIAN WITH
A PSYCHO-TRICORDER, PLEASE.
USE THESE COORDINATES.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
COORDINATES RECEIVED.
KIRK OUT.
McCoy: PREFECT,
THE PSYCHO-TRICORDER
WILL REQUIRE PRIVACY
IN ORDER TO BE EFFECTIVE.
HMM. THERE IS A SMALL
CHAMBER BELOW THIS ROOM.
PERHAPS THAT WILL SUFFICE.
CAPTAIN...
NEWS OF THIS...
FRIGHTFUL MURDER...
IS SPREADING
AMONG MY PEOPLE.
THEY ARE GREATLY DISTURBED.
I HAVE ALREADY
HEARD TALK
OF CLOSING ARGELIUS
TO SPACE VEHICLES.
WELL, THAT WOULD BE
MOST UNFORTUNATE.
ARGELIAN HOSPITALITY
IS WELL-KNOWN,
AS WELL AS ITS
STRATEGIC IMPORTANCE
AS A SPACE PORT.
YES. I BELIEVE
IT'S THE ONLY ONE
IN THE QUADRANT.
CAPTAIN.
Hengist: UH, THERE
ARE OTHER PEOPLE
WE SHOULD QUESTION.
UH, PERHAPS I
SHOULD GO EXPEDITE
THEIR ARRIVAL HERE.
YES, PLEASE DO SO,
MR. HENGIST.
ANYONE WITH ANY CONNECTION
WITH THIS MURDER
SHOULD BE PRESENT
AT THE CEREMONY.
LIEUTENANT KAREN TRACY
REPORTING AS ORDERED,
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT, I WANT
A 24-HOUR REGRESSIVE MEMORY
CHECK MADE ON MR. SCOTT.
Tracy: YES, CAPTAIN.
WHERE SHALL I SET UP?
IF YOU WILL JUST
FOLLOW ME, LIEUTENANT.
SCOTTY,
COOPERATE COMPLETELY
WITH LIEUTENANT TRACY.
MAYBE WE CAN CLEAR
THIS THING UP.
I CERTAINLY
HOPE SO, SIR.
I CAN'T STAND
THIS NOT KNOWING.
CAPTAIN, UNDER
NORMAL CONDITIONS,
SCOTTY WOULD HAVE
NEVER DONE SUCH A THING.
WELL, THAT BLOW
ON THE HEAD--
IT COULD PUT
ALL HIS PREVIOUS
BEHAVIOR PATTERNS
INTO THE JUNK HEAP.
OF COURSE, THERE'S
ANOTHER POSSIBILITY.
EXPLAIN.
HYSTERICAL AMNESIA.
WHEN A MAN FEELS GUILTY
ABOUT SOMETHING,
SOMETHING TOO TERRIBLE
TO REMEMBER,
HE BLOTS IT OUT
OF HIS CONSCIOUS MEMORY.
ARE YOU READY, SYBO?
I AM READY.
MAY I HAVE
THE KNIFE, PLEASE?
CERTAINLY.
AMONG OTHER GIFTS,
SYBO HAS THE ABILITY
TO RECEIVE IMPRESSIONS
FROM INANIMATE OBJECTS.
DO YOU HAVE IT,
CAPTAIN?
THE KNIFE?
NO.
BUT I PUT IT HERE
WHEN WE ARRIVED.
IT'S GONE.
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
SCOTTY.
SHE'S DEAD, JIM...
JUST LIKE THE OTHER ONE.
STABBED...
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
DRINK THIS.
[SNAPS FINGERS]
AN ARGELIAN
STIMULANT, DOCTOR.
QUITE EFFECTIVE
AND QUITE HARMLESS.
GO AHEAD, SCOTTY.
UH...LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN?
WHERE'S--
Kirk: LIEUTENANT TRACY
IS DEAD, SCOTT.
YOU WERE FOUND ALONE
IN THE ROOM.
DEAD? BUT, UH--
WHAT HAPPENED
DOWN THERE?
I WAS...
SITTING THERE.
SHE WAS TAKING
THE READINGS...
AND NOW I'M
SITTING HERE.
IS THAT ALL
THAT HAPPENED?
I TELL YOU,
I DON'T REMEMBER.
I MUST HAVE
PASSED OUT.
IT COULD BE, JIM--
THAT HEAD INJURY.
YEAH...
THINK, SCOTTY.
CAPTAIN,
I'VE BEEN TRYING.
I CAN'T EVEN BELIEVE
THIS IS REALLY HAPPENING.
THERE'S NO WAY
INTO THAT PLACE
FROM UP HERE.
PREFECT,
IS THERE
ANOTHER ENTRANCE
TO THAT CHAMBER?
YES, THERE'S A DOOR
THAT LEADS INTO
THE GARDEN,
BUT THAT'S BEEN
LOCKED FOR YEARS.
LOCKS CAN BE
PICKED, JIM.
CHECK IT.
UH, PREFECT, UH,
BOTH OF THESE MEN WERE
AT THE CAFE THE NIGHT
OF THE MURDER.
WHERE HAVE THEY BEEN
DURING THE PAST
FEW MINUTES?
UH, CAPTAIN, IF YOU
DON'T MIND, PLEASE.
Kirk: THERE'S BEEN
ANOTHER MURDER,
HENGIST--
ONE OF MY CREW.
THE SAME
AS KARA.
WHY, TH-THAT'S
TERRIBLE. I...
UH, YOU,
MY MEN PICKED YOU
UP NEAR HERE.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
PLEASE,
I KNOW NOTHING ABOUT IT.
I DIDN'T KILL ANYONE.
WELL, HOW WAS
THE GIRL KILLED?
STABBED,
AND THERE'S NO SIGN
OF THE WEAPON.
IF ONLY I HAD FACILITY--
YOU.
YOU WERE A MUSICIAN
AT THE CAFE.
YOU PLAYED FOR
THE MURDERED GIRL.
SINCE SHE WAS
A LITTLE GIRL,
SHE DANCED FOR ME.
SHE WAS
MY DAUGHTER.
PREFECT,
HOW COULD A THING LIKE THIS
HAVE HAPPENED HERE?
THE MAN WHO DID IT
MUST BE FOUND.
HE MUST BE PUNISHED.
AND YOU.
YOU LEFT THE CAFE
BEFORE SCOTT
AND KARA.
IS THIS TRUE?
WHO ARE YOU?
MORLA OF CANTABA STREET,
PREFECT.
I WAS THERE.
I HAVE NOTHING TO HIDE.
DID YOU KNOW KARA?
OF COURSE
HE KNEW HER.
THEY WERE
TO BE MARRIED,
BUT HE BEHAVED
DISGRACEFUL,
UNHEARD OF!
HE WAS...JEALOUS OF HER.
THAT IS VERY
DISQUIETING.
I KNOW IT WAS WRONG,
PREFECT,
BUT I JUST COULDN'T
HELP MYSELF.
I LOVED HER,
AND WHEN SHE WENT OVER TO
THE TABLE WITH THESE MEN,
I JUST COULD NOT
STAND TO WATCH,
SO I LEFT, I WENT HOME.
JEALOUSY HAS OFTEN
BEEN A MOTIVE
FOR MURDER.
YES, I KNOW.
THAT IS WHY THE
EMOTION IS SO STRONGLY
DISAPPROVED OF HERE.
PREFECT, I DIDN'T
KILL ANYONE, I COULDN'T!
WE SHALL SEE,
MORLA.
SORRY, JIM.
THE LOCK MAY
OR MAY NOT
HAVE BEEN PICKED.
BE HARD TO TELL,
EVEN WITH
THE TRICORDER.
CAN YOU PROVE
YOU WENT DIRECTLY HOME?
UH, CAPTAIN, UH,
MAY I CONTINUE WITH
THE QUESTIONS, PLEASE?
WELL, GET ON WITH IT, MAN.
JUST DON'T STAND THERE.
Prefect:
CAPTAIN, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE BEHAVING
VERY MUCH LIKE A MAN
WHO IS DESPERATELY
TRYING ANYTHING
TO SAVE HIS FRIEND.
WOULD YOU BE
AS DESPERATE
TO SAVE ARGELIUS
AS A SPACE PORT
FOR YOUR STARFLEET?
WELL, OF COURSE I'M TRYING
TO SAVE MY FRIEND...
IF HE'S INNOCENT, AND HE
HASN'T BEEN PROVEN GUILTY.
UH, NEED I REMIND YOU OF
THE CIRCUMSTANCES, CAPTAIN?
IN BOTH CASES,
YOUR FRIEND SCOTT WAS
DISCOVERED OVER THE BODY
AND LATER CLAIMED
TO REMEMBER NOTHING.
Sybo:
I AM READY, JARIS.
GENTLEMEN,
SIT DOWN, PLEASE.
ON ONE CONDITION,
PREFECT--
THAT THE ROOM BE SEALED
SO THAT NO ONE CAN LEAVE
OR ENTER WHILE
THE CEREMONY IS GOING ON.
THE ROOM
IS SEALED.
CAPTAIN, DO YOU MEAN
MY NECK IS GOING
TO HAVE TO DEPEND
ON SOME SPOOKY
MUMBO-JUMBO?
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
MAY I HAVE A WORD WITH YOU?
YES.
EXCUSE ME, GENTLEMEN.
YES, MR. SPOCK?
CONCERNING THE SITUATION
YOU RELATED TO US--
IN MY OPINION,
THE ARGELIAN
EMPATHIC CONTACT IS AN
INTERESTING PHENOMENON,
BUT THE TECHNIQUE
IS NOT SOUND ENOUGH
TO RISK A MAN'S LIFE.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST,
MR. SPOCK?
SIMPLY THAT WE BEAM
MR. SCOTT ONBOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE"
AND EMPLOY OUR COMPUTERS
TO LEARN THE TRUTH.
THESE ARE A PROUD PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE THEIR OWN CUSTOMS,
THEIR OWN LAWS,
AND WHILE WE'RE HERE,
WE'RE SUBJECT TO THEM.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY IMPERATIVE
THIS MATTER BE RESOLVED
ACCORDING TO ARGELIAN LAW.
IS THAT CLEAR?
QUITE CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T LIKE IT ANY MORE
THAN YOU DO, SPOCK,
BUT THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO ABOUT IT.
KIRK OUT.
Sybo:
LET US BEGIN.
LET THE CIRCLE
NOT BE BROKEN.
CONCENTRATE
UPON THE FLAME
WHICH BURNS
UPON THE ALTAR OF TRUTH.
YES...
THERE IS SOMETHING HERE...
SOMETHING TERRIBLE.
I FEEL ITS PRESENCE--
FEAR, ANGER, HATRED.
ANGER FEEDS THE FLAME.
OH...
OHH...
THERE IS EVIL HERE,
MONSTROUS,
TERRIBLE EVIL,
CONSUMING HUNGER,
HATRED OF ALL THAT LIVES,
HATRED OF WOMEN,
A HUNGER
THAT NEVER DIES.
IT IS STRONG,
OVERPOWERING,
AN ANCIENT TERROR.
IT HAS A NAME--
BERATIS, KESLA,
REDJAC!
DEVOURING ALL LIFE,
ALL LIGHT.
A HUNGER
THAT WILL NEVER DIE!
REDJAC!
AAH!
THREE MURDERS...
AND SCOTTY THE ONLY
POSSIBLE ANSWER
EACH TIME.
I DON'T CARE WHAT
THE CIRCUMSTANCES
INDICATE, JIM.
SCOTTY SIMPLY COULD
NOT HAVE DONE IT.
NORMALLY, NO,
BUT THAT BLOW
ON HIS HEAD--
AH, NO, CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, I'M SORRY.
YOU DON'T EVEN
REMEMBER WHETHER
YOU DID IT OR NOT.
I AGREE WITH YOU,
CAPTAIN.
I AM PERFECTLY SATISFIED
MR. SCOTT IS GUILTY.
BUT NOT
RESPONSIBLE.
THAT IS UNPROVEN, SIR.
WE CAN PROVE IT
IF HE'S INSANE.
GENTLEMEN! PLEASE.
HOW COULD ANY MAN DO
SUCH MONSTROUS THINGS?
Kirk:
THAT'S WHAT WE HOPE
TO FIND OUT, SIR.
MR. SCOTT--
SIR, I SWEAR TO YOU
I DID NOT
KILL YOUR WIFE
OR THE OTHER LADIES.
BY YOUR OWN ADMISSION,
YOU DON'T KNOW WHETHER
YOU DID OR DIDN'T.
YOUR SO-CALLED
FAILING MEMORY--
MR. HENGIST.
ON THE "ENTERPRISE,"
WE CAN MAKE
A RECORDING
OF THE REGISTRATIONS
OF MR. SCOTT'S
CONSCIOUS AND
SUBCONSCIOUS MIND.
AND THEY WILL
TELL US
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM
IN THE RECENT PAST.
McCoy: THERE WOULD BE
NO ROOM FOR DOUBT.
WE WOULD KNOW,
AND AFTER ALL, THAT'S
WHAT WE'RE AFTER,
ISN'T IT, PREFECT, TO KNOW?
Prefect:
YOU, SIR, CLAIM
TO REMEMBER NOTHING
ABOUT THE MURDERS.
AYE.
IF THIS IS SO,
YOU MAY HAVE KILLED
WITHOUT KNOWING IT.
WILL YOUR MACHINES
TELL US THIS?
NO DOUBT
WILL REMAIN.
VERY WELL.
WE WILL GO
TO YOUR SHIP...
AND HE WHO IS GUILTY
WILL FACE
THE ANCIENT PENALTIES,
BARBARIC AND HORRIBLE
THOUGH THEY MAY BE.
THE ANCIENT PENALTY
FOR MURDER
WAS DEATH BY SLOW TORTURE.
THAT LAW HAS
NEVER BEEN CHANGED.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT,
MR. SCOTT?
AYE...
I UNDERSTAND.
"CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3615.4.
"WITH MR. SCOTT IN
A TECHNICAL STATE OF ARREST,
"WE HAVE BEAMED ABOARD
THE 'ENTERPRISE'
TO CONTINUE
THE INVESTIGATION."
EACH TESTIFIER
WILL SIT HERE,
PLACE HIS HAND
ON THIS PLATE.
ANY DEVIATION
FROM THE FACTUAL TRUTH
WILL BE
IMMEDIATELY DETECTED
AND RELAYED TO THIS COMPUTER,
WHICH WILL
IN TURN NOTIFY US.
DR. McCOY HAS ALREADY
FED THE COMPUTER
HIS MEDICAL REPORTS.
OUR LABORATORY EXPERTS
ARE EXAMINING THE MURDER WEAPON
AND WILL GIVE THEIR DATA TO
THE COMPUTERS FOR ANALYSIS.
SHALL WE BEGIN?
MR. SCOTT,
WILL YOU TAKE THE STAND?
COMPUTER,
IDENTIFY
VERIFICATION.
Computer: WORKING.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
MONTGOMERY SCOTT.
SERIAL NUMBER
SE19754T.
VERIFIED.
SUBJECT'S PRESENT
PHYSICAL CONDITION.
WORKING.
SUBJECT RECENTLY RECEIVED
SEVERE BLOW ON SKULL.
DAMAGE HEALING.
SOME PERIPHERAL
ABNORMALITIES.
SUFFICIENT
ABNORMALITIES
TO ACCOUNT
FOR PERIODS
OF FUNCTIONAL
AMNESIA?
WORKING.
NEGATIVE.
CAPTAIN, I DON'T SEE
HOW THAT CAN BE.
UNLESS SCOTTY'S
LYING ABOUT HIS LOSS
OF MEMORY.
I'M NOT LYING, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T REMEMBER A THING
ABOUT THE FIRST TWO MURDERS.
COMPUTER, ACCURACY SCAN.
Computer: SUBJECT RELAYING
ACCURATE ACCOUNT.
NO PHYSIOLOGICAL CHANGES.
CAPTAIN...
I DIDN'T BLACK OUT WHEN
MR. JARIS' WIFE WAS KILLED.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY,
LET'S HAVE IT.
WE WERE HOLDING HANDS.
WHEN THE LIGHTS WENT OUT,
THE CIRCLE WAS BROKEN.
I HEARD THE POOR LADY
SCREAM, AND I WAS--
I WAS NEAR THE HEAD
OF THE TABLE ANYWAY.
I WENT TOWARD HER, BUT...
THERE WAS...
SOMETHING IN MY WAY.
SOMETHING?
YOU MEAN, SOMEONE.
NO, CAPTAIN, SOME...
THING.
COLD, IT WAS,
LIKE A...
STINKING DRAFT OUT
OF A SLAUGHTERHOUSE,
BUT IT WASN'T R--
REALLY THERE.
LIKE A--
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
COMPUTER?
SUBJECT RELAYING
ACCURATE ACCOUNT.
NO PHYSIOLOGICAL CHANGES.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S HIT IT
ON THE HEAD.
SCOTTY...
DID YOU KILL SYBO?
NO, CAPTAIN.
THAT I'M SURE OF.
HE'S BEEN SAYING THAT
RIGHT ALONG.
MEANS NO MORE NOW
THAN IT DID BEFORE.
SCOTTY, LIE TO ME.
HOW OLD ARE YOU?
UH...22, SIR.
INACCURATE. INACCURATE.
DATA IN ERROR.
AFTER THE LIGHTS
WENT OUT, MR. SCOTT,
WHO WAS HOLDING YOUR HAND?
MORLA ON THE ONE SIDE
AND YOU ON THE OTHER, SIR.
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN
ANYTHING, CAPTAIN.
WITH A ROOM THAT SMALL--
THE LIGHTS WERE OUT--
ANYONE WOULD'VE HAD TIME
TO KILL THE LADY.
Hengist:
BUT I REMIND YOU, WE FOUND
MR. SCOTT HOLDING HER IN
HIS ARMS, THE KNIFE ST--
I'M SORRY, SIR,
BUT I MUST.
THE KNIFE STILL IN HER BACK
AND BLOOD ON HIS HANDS.
THE VERIFIER SHOWED THAT
HE WAS TELLING THE TRUTH
WHEN HE SAID
HE DIDN'T KILL HER.
THERE WERE TWO OTHER
WOMEN MURDERED.
MR. SCOTT...
DID YOU KILL KARA?
I DON'T REMEMBER.
DID YOU KILL
LIEUTENANT TRACY?
[SIGHS]
I DON'T REMEMBER.
COMPUTER, ACCURACY SCAN.
SUBJECT RELAYING
ACCURATE ACCOUNT.
NO PHYSIOLOGICAL CHANGES.
ALL THAT PROVES IS THAT
HE'S TELLING THE TRUTH
WHEN HE SAYS
HE DOESN'T REMEMBER.
THIS IS A WASTE OF TIME.
AFTER WE TAKE
THE TESTIMONY HERE,
WE'LL RUN
A PSYCHO-TRICORDER
ANALYSIS OF
MR. SCOTT'S MEMORY,
WHICH IS WHAT WE WANTED
TO DO ON THE SURFACE.
THAT WILL GIVE US
A COMPLETE RECORD.
WILL THAT SATISFY YOU,
MR. HENGIST?
WELL,
IF YOU CAN CONVINCE ME
THAT THE MACHINE
IS INCAPABLE OF ERROR
AND IF IT SHOWS
HE DID NOT KILL THE WOMEN.
THERE WILL BE NO ERROR.
AS FOR THE REST OF IT,
THE READINGS WILL SHOW.
I THINK YOU CAN
STEP DOWN NOW,
MR. SCOTT,
IF THERE ARE
NO OBJECTIONS.
I OBJECT TO THE
ENTIRE PROCEDURE.
MR. HENGIST,
WE ARE HERE ON
MY AUTHORITY.
WE WILL
COOPERATE.
PREFECT,
I KNOW YOU MEAN WELL,
BUT I'VE HAD EXPERIENCE--
FOR THE TIME BEING,
WE WILL ACCEPT
CAPTAIN KIRK'S
EXPLANATION
OF THE MACHINE'S
ACCURACY AS FACTUAL.
I DO, HOWEVER, RESERVE
TO MYSELF THE RIGHT
TO MAKE THE FINAL
DETERMINATION.
WE CAN ASK NO MORE.
MR. MORLA, WILL YOU
TAKE THE STAND?
WHERE WERE YOU AT THE TIME
THAT KARA WAS MURDERED?
I'M NOT SURE.
WALKING HOME, I--I ASSUME.
I WAS ANGRY.
ANGER IS
A RELATIVE STATE, SIR.
WERE YOU ANGRY ENOUGH
TO DO VIOLENCE?
I'VE NEVER DONE VIOLENCE
IN MY LIFE.
I DON'T THINK
THAT I COULD.
YOU'VE GOT TO BELIEVE ME.
I WOULDN'T KILL HER.
I COULDN'T.
I LOVED HER,
AND SHE LOVED ME.
THAT'S NOT TRUE!
HE MIGHT THINK
SHE LOVED HIM,
BUT SHE DIDN'T.
SHE TOLD ME.
HE WAS JEALOUS
ALL THE TIME.
THEY FOUGHT CONSTANTLY.
DID YOU KILL
LIEUTENANT TRACY?
NO.
DID YOU KILL SYBO?
COMPUTER,
VERIFICATION SCAN.
SUBJECT RELAYING
ACCURATE ACCOUNT,
THOUGH SOME STATEMENTS
SUBJECTIVE.
NO PHYSIOLOGICAL CHANGES.
ALL RIGHT, MR. MORLA,
I THINK YOU CAN
STEP DOWN NOW.
SYBO SPOKE OF A HUNGER
THAT NEVER DIED,
SOMETHING THAT THRIVES
ON...FEAR,
TERROR, DEATH.
MR. SPOCK, MAYBE
WE'RE GOING ABOUT IT
THE WRONG WAY.
LET'S ASSUME THAT SYBO
WAS A SENSITIVE--
THAT SHE DID
SENSE SOMETHING,
SOMETHING EVIL.
SENSITIVITY OF CERTAIN
ARGELIAN WOMEN
IS A DOCUMENTED FACT,
CAPTAIN.
MY POOR SYBO'S TALENT
WAS GENUINE, GENTLEMEN.
WHAT SHE TOLD YOU
WAS TRUE.
ALL RIGHT, THEN,
WHAT WAS IT
SHE SAID, EXACTLY?
MONSTROUS EVIL,
ANCIENT TERROR...
THAT DEVOURS
ALL LIFE AND LIGHT.
SHE SAID SOMETHING
ELSE--WORDS THAT
DIDN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
YES.
REDJAC...
BERATIS...
AND, UH...KESLA.
OBSCURE,
MEANINGLESS WORDS.
TO US, PERHAPS,
BUT TO THE COMPUTER?
AH, MR. SPOCK,
CHECK THEM OUT.
COMPUTER,
LINGUISTIC BANK.
DEFINITION
OF FOLLOWING WORD--
REDJAC.
WORKING.
NEGATIVE FINDING.
THERE IS NO SUCH WORD
IN THE LINGUISTICS BANK?
Computer: AFFIRMATIVE.
SCAN ALL
OTHER BANKS.
WORKING.
AFFIRMATIVE.
A PROPER NAME.
DEFINE.
REDJAC.
SOURCE--
EARTH, 19th CENTURY.
LANGUAGE--ENGLISH.
NICKNAME FORMAT--
MURDERER OF WOMEN.
OTHER EARTH SYNONYMS--
JACK THE RIPPER.
JACK THE RIPPER?
WELL, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
HE LIVED HUNDREDS
OF YEARS AGO.
A MAN COULDN'T SURVIVE
ALL THESE CENTURIES.
JUST BEFORE
SHE DIED,
MY WIFE SAID...
IT IS A HUNGER
THAT NEVER...DIES.
BUT ALL MEN DIE.
YES, ALL MEN DIE,
AND JACK THE RIPPER
COULDN'T BE ALIVE
IF HE WERE A MAN,
BUT EVERYTHING
WE'VE UNCOVERED POINTS
TO JACK THE RIPPER, WHICH IS
AN IMPOSSIBILITY, ISN'T IT?
OR IS IT?
HUMANS AND HUMANOIDS MAKE UP
ONLY A SMALL PERCENTAGE
OF THE LIFE FORMS
WE KNOW OF.
THERE ARE ENTITIES
POSSESSED OF EXTREMELY
LONG LIFE SPANS,
VIRTUALLY IMMORTAL.
WE KNOW THAT...
SOMEONE OR...
SOMETHING...KILLED
THREE WOMEN.
IF IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
FOR IT TO BE HUMAN,
IT HAS TO BE SOMETHING
ELSE, SOMETHING
DRIVEN TO KILL.
BUT SYBO SAID THAT
IT FEEDS ON DEATH.
IN THE STRICT SCIENTIFIC
SENSE, DOCTOR,
WE ALL FEED ON DEATH,
EVEN VEGETARIANS.
YES, BUT IT SAID
MORE THAN THAT;
NOT JUST DEATH, BUT FEAR.
SAID IT ALSO FEEDS
ON FEAR.
Spock: WHICH WOULD
TEND TO SUPPORT
THE PROPOSITION
THAT THE MURDERER
WAS NOT HUMAN.
DERIVING SUSTENANCE
FROM EMOTION
IS NOT UNKNOWN
IN THE GALAXY,
AND FEAR IS AMONG
THE STRONGEST
AND MOST VIOLENT
OF THE EMOTIONS.
SURELY, PREFECT,
THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
SOMEONE--
SOME MAN HAS KILLED
THREE WOMEN.
WE HAVE THE PRIME SUSPECT
IN OUR HANDS.
ARE WE GOING TO LET HIM GO
AND START CHASING GHOSTS?
NO, MR. HENGIST,
NOT GHOSTS.
POSSIBLY NOT HUMAN,
BUT NOT GHOSTS.
MR. SPOCK, CHECK OUT
THE POSSIBILITIES.
COMPUTER, DIGEST
LOG RECORDINGS
FOR PAST FIVE
SOLAR MINUTES.
CORRELATE
HYPOTHESES.
COMPARE WITH
LIFE FORMS REGISTER.
QUESTION--
COULD SUCH AN ENTITY
WITHIN DISCUSSED
LIMITS EXIST
IN THIS GALAXY?
Computer: THE DRELLA
OF ALPHA CARINAE V
DERIVED NOURISHMENT
FROM THE EMOTION OF LOVE.
THERE IS
SUFFICIENT PRECEDENT
FOR EXISTENCE OF CREATURE,
NATURE UNKNOWN,
WHICH COULD EXIST
ON EMOTION OF FEAR.
COMPUTER, EXTRAPOLATE
MOST LIKELY COMPOSITION
OF SUCH ENTITY.
Computer: WORKING.
TO MEET WITH SPECIFIED
REQUIREMENTS,
ENTITY WOULD EXIST WITHOUT
FORM IN CONVENTIONAL SENSE.
MOST PROBABLE--
MASS OF ENERGY
OF HIGHLY COHESIVE
ELECTROMAGNETIC FIELD.
COMPUTER...
COULD
THE DESCRIBED ENTITY
ASSUME PHYSICAL FORM?
Computer:
AFFIRMATIVE. PRECEDENT--
MELLITUS, CLOUD CREATURE
OF ALPHA MAJORIS 1.
FAIRY TALES.
GHOSTS AND GOBLINS.
Kirk: NO, I HAVE SEEN
THE MELLITUS MYSELF.
IN ITS NATURAL STATE,
IT'S GASEOUS.
WHEN IT'S AT REST,
IT'S SOLID.
MR. SPOCK, LET'S ASSUME THE
EXISTENCE OF THIS CREATURE.
I POINT OUT THAT
JACK THE RIPPER SLEW AT WILL
IN THE HEART OF THE MOST
POPULOUS CITY OF OLD EARTH
AND WAS NEVER IDENTIFIED.
DOESN'T SEEM LIKELY,
DOES IT?
I SUGGEST THE POSSIBILITY
OF A HYPNOTIC SCREEN,
WHICH BLINDS ALL
BUT THE VICTIM
TO THE PRESENCE
OF THE KILLER.
IS THAT
POSSIBLE?
EXTREMELY POSSIBLE;
THERE ARE MANY SUCH
EXAMPLES THAT EXIST
IN NATURE.
WELL, THIS IS FANTASY!
WE ALL KNOW THE MURDERER IS
SITTING RIGHT HERE WITH US.
I MEAN, YOU'RE TRYING
TO CLOUD THE ISSUE.
I'VE GOT A MIND TO--
I AM SATISFIED
THE COURSE
OF THIS INVESTIGATION
IS VALID ENOUGH.
PLEASE BE SEATED,
MR. HENGIST.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK,
WHAT DO WE HAVE?
A CREATURE WITHOUT FORM
THAT FEEDS ON HORROR AND FEAR,
THAT MUST ASSUME
A PHYSICAL SHAPE
TO KILL.
AND, I SUSPECT,
PREYS ON WOMEN
BECAUSE WOMEN
ARE MORE EASILY
AND MORE DEEPLY
TERRIFIED,
GENERATING
MORE SHEER HORROR THAN
THE MALE OF THE SPECIES.
COMPUTER,
CRIMINOLOGICAL FILES.
CASES OF UNSOLVED
MASS MURDERS
OF WOMEN
SINCE JACK THE RIPPER.
Computer: WORKING. 1932.
SHANGHAI, CHINA, EARTH--
SEVEN WOMEN
KNIFED TO DEATH.
1974.
KIEV, U.S.S.R., EARTH--
FIVE WOMEN
KNIFED TO DEATH.
2105. MARTIAN COLONIES--
EIGHT WOMEN
KNIFED TO DEATH.
2156.
HELIOPOLIS,
ALPHA ERIDANI II--
10 WOMEN
KNIFED TO DEATH.
THERE ARE ADDITIONAL
EXAMPLES.
CAPTAIN, THOSE PLACES
ARE ALIGNED DIRECTLY
BETWEEN ARGELIUS
AND EARTH.
YES.
WHEN MAN MOVED OUT
INTO THE GALAXY,
THAT THING MUST'VE
MOVED WITH HIM.
COMPUTER, IDENTIFY
THE PROPER NAMES
KESLA AND BERATIS.
Computer: WORKING.
KESLA--NAME GIVEN
TO UNIDENTIFIED
MASS MURDERER OF WOMEN
ON PLANET DENEB II.
BERATIS--
NAME GIVEN TO UNIDENTIFIED
MASS MURDERER OF WOMEN
ON PLANET RIGEL IV.
ADDITIONAL DATA--
MURDERS ON RIGEL IV OCCURRED
ONE SOLAR YEAR AGO.
YOU COME FROM RIGEL IV.
WELL, MANY PEOPLE DO.
IT'S NOT A CRIME.
NO, BUT WHAT WE'RE
INVESTIGATING IS.
WOULD YOU MIND TAKING
THE STAND, MR. HENGIST?
WHY, I WILL NOT.
MR. HENGIST.
PREFECT,
THIS HAS GONE FAR ENOUGH.
I WILL NOT TAKE THE STAND.
I CAN APPRECIATE
YOUR POSITION, SIR.
YOU ARE IN CHARGE OF
CIVIL DISTURBANCES LOCALLY.
IF YOU ARE THE ENTITY
FOR WHICH WE SEARCH,
WHAT BETTER POSITION
FROM WHICH TO KILL
WITH IMPUNITY?
AND JUST AFTER YOU
LEFT JARIS' HOUSE,
WE DISCOVERED
THE MURDER KNIFE
WAS MISSING.
Kirk: AND YOU WERE
UNACCOUNTED FOR
WHEN LIEUTENANT TRACY
WAS MURDERED.
Spock:
AN ENTITY WHICH FEEDS
ON FEAR AND TERROR
WOULD FIND A PERFECT
HUNTING GROUND ON ARGELIUS,
A PLANET WITHOUT VIOLENCE,
WHERE THE INHABITANTS
ARE AS PEACEFUL AS SHEEP.
THE ENTITY WOULD BE
AS A HUNGRY WOLF
IN THAT FOLD.
GENTLEMEN, I KNOW
SOMETHING OF THE LAW.
YOU'RE ENGAGING
IN SHEER SPECULATION.
PERHAPS.
MR. SPOCK...
THE MURDER WEAPON.
Spock: COMPUTER,
REPORT ON ANALYSIS
OF EXHIBIT "A."
Computer: WORKING.
EXHIBIT "A" ON VISUAL.
COMPOSITION OF BLADE--
BORIDIUM.
COMPOSITION OF HANDLE--
MURINITE.
DETAILS OF CARVING
ON HANDLE CONFORM
TO FOLK ART FORMS,
INDICATING PLACE OF ORIGIN.
SPECIFY POINT
OF ORIGIN.
ARTIFACT PRODUCED
BY HILL PEOPLE
OF ARGUS RIVER REGION,
PLANET RIGEL IV.
NOW, THEN, MR. HENGIST...
HE'S DEAD, JIM.
BUT THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
[HENGIST'S VOICE]
REDJAC! REDJAC! REDJAC!
REDJAC! REDJAC!
[MANIACAL LAUGHTER]
THE COMPUTER WILL NOT
RESPOND TO THESE CONTROLS.
THE ENTITY IS UNQUESTIONABLY
CONTROLLING IT.
AND THE COMPUTER
CONTROLS THE SHIP.
REDJAC! REDJAC!
[MANIACAL LAUGHTER]
SCOTTY, GIVE ME A HAND.
NO USE, CAPTAIN.
THE BYPASS CIRCUITS
ARE BLOCKED.
AUDIO CUTOFF, SPOCK.
CAPTAIN!
Woman:
WHAT'S HAPPENING, CAPTAIN?
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
Kirk: IT MEANS
THAT THING CAN CONTROL
THE ENTIRE OPERATION
OF THE SHIP, INCLUDING
THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
YOU MEAN
IT COULD KILL US ALL?
INDEED IT WILL TRY,
BUT NOT IMMEDIATELY.
WE KNOW IT FEEDS
ON FEAR AND TERROR.
THERE ARE
NEARLY 440 HUMANS
ABOARD THIS SHIP.
SURELY IT WILL TRY
TO BREED FEAR AND
TERROR BEFORE IT KILLS.
ALL HANDS,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
STAY AT YOUR POSTS.
REMAIN CALM.
CAPTAIN OUT.
BONES...
WHAT'S
THE SEDATIVE SITUATION?
I'VE GOT SOME STUFF
THAT WOULD TRANQUILIZE
AN ACTIVE VOLCANO.
GOOD. START DISTRIBUTION
IMMEDIATELY.
THE LONGER WE CAN
HOLD BACK THAT FEAR,
THE MORE TIME WE'LL HAVE
TO GET THAT THING OUT
OF THE COMPUTER.
PREFECT,
YOU'LL ALL BE SAFER HERE.
SPOCK, COME WITH ME.
SPOCK, DON'T YOU HAVE
A COMPULSORY SCAN UNIT
BUILT INTO
THE COMPUTER BANKS?
YES, WE DO, CAPTAIN,
BUT WITH THE ENTITY
IN CONTROL--
WELL, AREN'T
THERE CERTAIN
MATHEMATICAL PROBLEMS
WHICH SIMPLY
CANNOT BE SOLVED?
INDEED.
IF WE COULD FOCUS
THE ATTENTION OF THE
COMPUTER ON ONE OF THEM...
THAT OUGHT TO DO IT.
SPOCK!
APPARENTLY OUR FRIENDS
LEARN VERY QUICKLY.
TOO QUICKLY.
BRIDGE.
FREE FALL!
OUT OF CONTROL.
PUT IT ON MANUAL.
BRIDGE.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
THAT WAS DUE TO BE NEXT.
LIFE SUPPORT MALFUNCTION.
WE DON'T HAVE
MUCH TIME, CAPTAIN.
WELL, YOU SAID IT
YOURSELF, SPOCK,
IT WANTS TERROR,
NOT JUST DEATH.
CAPTAIN, THE LIFE
SUPPORT SYSTEM
OVERRIDE JAMMED.
ALL RIGHT, MAN YOUR
STATION, MR. SULU.
Sulu: AYE, SIR.
Entity: CAPTAIN KIRK!
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE WASTING YOUR TIME.
CUT THAT THING OFF.
YOU AND ALL ABOARD
YOUR SHIP
ARE ABOUT TO DIE!
TRY AND CUT
THAT THING OFF.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I HEARD A MALFUNCTION
THREATEN US.
MAN YOUR POST, MR. SULU.
PREPARE YOUR
MANUAL OVERRIDES.
YOU MAY NEED THEM.
AYE, SIR.
SPOCK.
NORMAL
ENVIRONMENTAL LEVELS
HAVE BEEN RESTORED,
CAPTAIN, BUT IT
WILL NOT LAST LONG,
A FEW HOURS AT BEST.
THAT SHOULD BE
ENOUGH TIME.
LET'S GET AT IT.
WHAT'S GOING ON,
CAPTAIN?
NEVER MIND, MR. SULU.
- TRANQUILIZER?
- YES, SIR.
EVERYONE,
INCLUDING YOURSELF.
YES, SIR.
Entity: YOU CANNOT
STOP ME NOW, CAPTAIN.
IT WILL DO YOU NO GOOD.
I CONTROL ALL CIRCUITS.
YOU CANNOT SILENCE ME.
YOU CANNOT REACH ME.
YOUR MANUAL OVERRIDES ARE
EXTREMELY LIMITED IN LIFE.
SPOCK?
PROCEEDING, CAPTAIN,
BUT I WILL NEED SOME TIME.
YES, I KNOW.
Entity: SOON ALL CONTROL
WILL BE RESTORED TO ME!
THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN DO
TO PREVENT IT!
IF YOU DESTROY THIS SHIP,
YOU DESTROY YOURSELF.
[MANIACAL LAUGHTER]
I AM WITHOUT ENDING.
I HAVE EXISTED
FROM THE DAWN OF TIME,
AND I SHALL LIVE
BEYOND ITS END!
I SHALL FEED,
AND THIS TIME,
I DO NOT NEED A KNIFE.
YOU WILL ALL DIE HORRIBLY,
IN SEARING PAIN!
IT IS ATTEMPTING
TO GENERATE TERROR, CAPTAIN.
I MAY CUT OFF YOUR OXYGEN
AND SUFFOCATE YOU!
[MANIACAL LAUGHTER]
CAPTAIN...
WHOEVER HE IS,
HE SURE TALKS
GLOOMY.
MAN YOUR POST, SULU.
IF ANY OF THE OTHER
SYSTEMS GO OUT, SWITCH
TO MANUAL OVERRIDE
AND ABOVE ALL...
DON'T BE AFRAID.
WITH AN ARMFUL
OF THIS STUFF,
I WOULDN'T BE AFRAID
OF A SUPERNOVA.
READY.
IMPLEMENT.
COMPUTER,
THIS IS A CLASS "A"
COMPULSORY DIRECTIVE.
COMPUTE TO THE LAST DIGIT
THE VALUE OF PI.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO!
NO, NO!
AS WE KNOW,
THE VALUE OF PI
IS A TRANSCENDENTAL FIGURE
WITHOUT RESOLUTION.
THE COMPUTER BANKS
WILL WORK ON THIS PROBLEM
TO THE EXCLUSION
OF ALL ELSE UNTIL WE
ORDER IT TO STOP.
YES, THAT SHOULD
KEEP THAT THING
BUSY FOR A WHILE.
THE ARGELIANS
WILL BE THE FIRST
TO PANIC.
LET'S GET BACK TO
THE BRIEFING ROOM.
HA HA HA HA!
I WONDER WHO IT IS
WE'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE AFRAID OF.
[LAUGHTER]
Scott: WELL, SIR?
I DOUBT VERY MUCH
WHETHER THE COMPUTERS
WILL BE INHABITED
BY MORE THAN A GROUP
OF FIGURES FOR A WHILE.
THERE IS RESISTANCE,
CAPTAIN,
BUT THE DIRECTIVE
IS SUCCEEDING.
BANK AFTER BANK
IS TURNING TO
THE PROBLEM.
IF YOU DRIVE IT OUT OF
THE COMPUTERS, IT'LL JUST
HAVE TO GO SOMEWHERE ELSE.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
WELL, I'M ALMOST FINISHED--
JUST JARIS AND ME.
[MANIACAL LAUGHTER]
[LAUGHTER FADES]
COMPLETE COMPUTER
CONTROL, CAPTAIN.
THE ENTITY HAS FLED.
YES, BUT WHERE TO?
BONES, WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF THAT THING ENTERED
A TRANQUILIZED BODY?
WELL, IT MIGHT TAKE UP
KNITTING, NOTHING MORE
VIOLENT THAN THAT.
AND YOU SAY EVERYONE'S HAD
A SHOT BUT YOU AND JARIS?
AND YOU AND MR. SPOCK,
CAPTAIN.
WELL,
I'M WILLING TO TAKE
A CHANCE ON MR. SPOCK.
BETTER GIVE YOURSELF
A SHOT, DOC.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK I OUGHT
TO STAY CLEAR.
DO AS I SAY.
ALL RIGHT.
[CHUCKLES]
EXTEND YOUR ARM, MR. JARIS.
[HENGIST'S VOICE]
NO, NO, KILL YOU ALL!
DIE! MAKE YOU SUFFER!
EVERYBODY KEEP BACK
OR I'LL KILL HER!
I'LL KILL HER!
KEEP BACK!
McCoy: BETTER BE CAREFUL.
YOU'RE GOING TO HURT
SOMEBODY WITH THAT THING.
OOH! HA HA HA!
YOU'LL SUFFER!
YOU'LL--
SUFF...
HA HA HA HA HA.
I'LL KILL
ALL OF YOU.
LET'S GET HIM TO
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM, QUICK!
[LAUGHING]
YOU'LL...
DIE, DIE, DIE.
EVERYBODY DIE.
HA HA!
[LAUGHING]
KILL, KILL, KILL YOU ALL.
[BEEPS]
DEEP SPACE.
FULL POWER.
WIDEST ANGLE
OF DISPERSION.
MAINTAIN.
NO NEED TO GET EXCITED,
CAPTAIN. I'LL DO IT.
YOU DO IT, SPOCK.
EVERYBODY DIES.
HA HA HA!
YOU WILL
ALL SUFFER.
YOU ALL...
Man: YOU DIDN'T HAVE
TO SHOVE ME, MR. SPOCK.
I'D HAVE GOTTEN ROUND TO IT.
[DOOR SLIDES OPEN]
WELL, JARIS
IS ALL RIGHT. HA HA!
NOW, WHAT DID YOU DO WITH
THAT THING, CAPTAIN, YOU
SEND IT BACK TO THE PLANET?
NO. WE BEAMED IT
OUT INTO OPEN
SPACE, SCOTTY,
WIDEST POSSIBLE
DISPERSION.
THE THING CAN'T DIE.
Spock:
POSSIBLY, DOCTOR.
ITS CONSCIOUSNESS MAY
CONTINUE FOR SOME TIME,
CONSISTING OF BILLIONS
OF SEPARATE BITS OF ENERGY,
FLOATING FOREVER IN SPACE,
POWERLESS.
BUT IT WILL DIE
FINALLY.
YOU SEEM
VERY HAPPY ABOUT
THE WHOLE THING.
WELL, WHY NOT?
FOR A WHILE THERE,
I DIDN'T KNOW WHETHER
I WAS INNOCENT OR GUILTY.
HA HA HA HA!
BONES, HOW LONG
WILL IT TAKE FOR
THIS TRANQUILIZER
TO WEAR OFF?
OH, I DON'T KNOW,
FIVE OR SIX HOURS.
I GAVE HIM A PRETTY
BIG SHOT, JIM.
YES, I CAN SEE THAT.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
FOR THE NEXT FIVE
OR SIX HOURS,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
THE HAPPIEST CREW
IN SPACE.
'COURSE, WE WON'T
GET MUCH WORK DONE.
CAPTAIN, SINCE YOU CAME
TO ARGELIUS TO REST,
I SUGGEST YOU TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF THE OPPORTUNITY.
THAT'S A SPLENDID IDEA,
MR. SPOCK.
I KNOW A CAFE
WHERE THE WOMEN ARE SO--
I KNOW THE PLACE, JIM.
LET'S GO SEE!
YOU GENTLEMEN,
IN YOUR CONDITION?
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
MR. SPOCK, THIS CAFE
HAS WOMEN THAT ARE SO...
NO, I GUESS NOT.
ALONE?
GENTLEMEN...
[LAUGHING]