DEEP SPACE STATION K-7
NOW WITHIN
SENSOR RANGE, CAPTAIN.
GOOD. MR. CHEKOV,
THIS FLIGHT IS
SUPPOSED TO PROVIDE
BOTH EXPERIENCE
AND KNOWLEDGE.
HOW CLOSE WILL
WE COME TO THE NEAREST
KLINGON OUTPOST
IF WE CONTINUE ON
OUR PRESENT COURSE?
ONE PARSEC, SIR.
CLOSE ENOUGH
TO SMELL THEM.
THAT IS ILLOGICAL, ENSIGN.
ODORS CANNOT TRAVEL
THROUGH THE VACUUM OF SPACE.
I WAS MAKING
A LITTLE JOKE, SIR.
EXTREMELY LITTLE,
ENSIGN.
MR. SPOCK, IMMEDIATE
PAST HISTORY
OF THE QUADRANT?
UNDER DISPUTE
BETWEEN THE TWO PARTIES
SINCE INITIAL CONTACT.
THE BATTLE OF DONATU-5
WAS FOUGHT NEAR HERE
23 SOLAR YEARS AGO.
INCONCLUSIVE.
ANALYSIS OF
DISPUTED AREA?
UNDEVELOPED.
SHERMAN'S PLANET
IS CLAIMED BY BOTH
SIDES--OUR FEDERATION
AND THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
WE DO HAVE THE BETTER CLAIM.
THE AREA
WAS FIRST MAPPED
BY THE FAMOUS
RUSSIAN ASTRONOMER
IVAN BORKOV
ALMOST 200--
JOHN BURKE.
BURKE, SIR?
I DON'T THINK SO.
I'M SURE IT WAS--
JOHN BURKE
WAS THE CHIEF ASTRONOMER
AT THE ROYAL ACADEMY
IN OLD BRITAIN AT THE TIME.
OH, ROYAL ACADEMY.
OH, WELL...
IS THE REST
OF YOUR HISTORY
THAT FAULTY, ENSIGN?
KEY POINTS OF DISPUTE?
UNDER THE TERMS OF
THE ORGANIAN PEACE TREATY,
ONE SIDE OR THE OTHER
MUST PROVE
IT CAN DEVELOP THE PLANET
MOST EFFICIENTLY.
AND UNFORTUNATELY,
THOUGH THE KLINGONS
ARE BRUTAL AND AGGRESSIVE,
THEY ARE MOST EFFICIENT.
I REMEMBER ONCE PETER
THE GREAT HAD A PROBLEM
LIKE THAT. HE--
Uhura: CAPTAIN?
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
A SUB-SPACE DISTRESS CALL.
PRIORITY CHANNEL. IT'S
FROM SPACE STATION K-7.
GO TO WARP FACTOR SIX.
CODE ONE EMERGENCY.
THAT'S A DISASTER CALL.
Uhura: THIS IS A RED ALERT.
MAN YOUR BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL HANDS.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4523.3.
DEEP SPACE STATION K-7
HAS ISSUED
A PRIORITY ONE CALL.
MORE THAN AN EMERGENCY,
IT SIGNALS
NEAR OR TOTAL DISASTER.
WE CAN ONLY ASSUME
THE KLINGONS
HAVE ATTACKED THE STATION.
WE'RE GOING IN
ARMED FOR BATTLE.
MAIN PHASERS ARMED
AND READY, SIR.
BUT THERE'S
NOTHING THERE.
JUST THE STATION.
PRIORITY ONE
DISTRESS CALL,
AND IT'S JUST
ABSOLUTELY PEACEFUL.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
BREAK SUB-SPACE SILENCE.
AYE, SIR.
THE CHANNEL'S
OPEN, SIR.
SPACE STATION K-7,
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
WHAT IS YOUR EMERGENCY?
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THIS IS MR. LURRY,
MANAGER OF K-7.
I MUST APOLOGIZE FOR
THE DISTRESS CALL.
MR. LURRY, YOU ISSUED
A PRIORITY ONE
DISTRESS CALL.
STATE THE NATURE
OF YOUR EMERGENCY.
UH...WELL, PERHAPS
YOU BETTER BEAM OVER.
I'LL TRY TO EXPLAIN.
YOU'LL TRY TO EXPLAIN.
YOU'D BETTER BE PREPARED
TO DO MORE THAN THAT.
KIRK OUT. MR. SPOCK,
I'LL NEED YOUR HELP.
MR. CHEKOV, MAINTAIN
BATTLE READINESS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA, SEE THAT
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
IS STANDING BY.
AYE, SIR.
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
STAND BY.
MR. LURRY, IF THERE WAS
NO EMERGENCY,
WHY DID YOU ISSUE
A PRIORITY ONE
DISTRESS CALL?
THAT WAS MY ORDER,
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THIS IS NILZ BARIS.
HE'S OUT FROM EARTH
TO TAKE CHARGE OF
THE DEVELOPMENT PROJECT
FOR SHERMAN'S PLANET.
AND THAT GIVES YOU
THE AUTHORITY
TO PUT AN ENTIRE QUADRANT
ON DEFENSE ALERT?
MR. BARIS
IS THE FEDERATION
UNDERSECRETARY
IN CHARGE OF
AGRICULTURAL AFFAIRS
IN THIS QUADRANT.
THAT GIVES HIM
THE AUTHORITY.
OH.
THIS IS MY ASSISTANT
ARNE DARVIN.
AND THIS IS
MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
MR. DARVIN.
AND NOW, CAPTAIN, I WANT ALL
AVAILABLE SECURITY GUARDS.
I WANT THEM POSTED AROUND
THE STORAGE COMPARTMENTS.
STORAGE COMPARTMENTS?
THE STORAGE
COMPARTMENTS
CONTAINING THE
QUADRO-TRITICALE.
THE WHAT? WHAT?
CAPTAIN.
WHAT'S...
QUADRO-TRITICALE?
WHEAT. SO WHAT?
QUADRO-TRITICALE
IS NOT WHEAT, CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE,
I WOULDN'T EXPECT
YOU OR MR. SPOCK
TO KNOW
ABOUT SUCH THINGS,
BUT QUADRO-TRITICALE
IS A RATHER--
QUADRO-TRITICALE IS
A HIGH-YIELD GRAIN,
4-LOBED HYBRID
OF WHEAT AND RYE.
A PERENNIAL, ALSO,
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN.
IT'S ROOT GRAIN,
TRITICALE,
CAN TRACE
ITS ANCESTRY
ALL THE WAY BACK
TO 20th CENTURY
CANADA--
MR. SPOCK, YOU'VE
MADE YOUR POINT.
QUADRO-TRITICALE IS
THE ONLY EARTH GRAIN
THAT WILL GROW
ON SHERMAN'S PLANET.
WE HAVE SEVERAL TONS
OF IT HERE ON THE STATION.
AND IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
THAT THAT GRAIN GET TO
SHERMAN'S PLANET SAFELY.
MR. BARIS THINKS
THAT KLINGON AGENTS
MAY TRY TO SABOTAGE IT.
YOU ISSUED A PRIORITY ONE
DISTRESS CALL
FOR A COUPLE OF
TONS OF WHEAT?
QUADRO-TRITICALE!
OF COURSE, CAPTAIN,
I REALIZE THAT WE--
MR. BARIS,
YOU SUMMONED
THE "ENTERPRISE"
WITHOUT
AN EMERGENCY.
YOU'LL TAKE FULL
RESPONSIBILITY
FOR IT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
Spock: MISUSE OF
THE PRIORITY
ONE CHANNEL
IS A FEDERATION
OFFENSE.
I DID NOT MISUSE
THE PRIORITY ONE CHANNEL.
I WANT THAT GRAIN
PROTECTED.
CAPTAIN, COULDN'T
YOU AT LEAST POST
A COUPLE OF GUARDS?
WE DO HAVE A LARGE NUMBER
OF SHIPS PASSING THROUGH.
IT WOULD
SEEM A LOGICAL
PRECAUTION, CAPTAIN.
THE SHERMAN'S PLANET
AFFAIR
IS OF
EXTREME IMPORTANCE
TO THE FEDERATION.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
"ENTERPRISE" HERE.
SECURE
FROM GENERAL QUARTERS.
AND BEAM DOWN TWO,
AND ONLY TWO,
SECURITY GUARDS.
HAVE THEM REPORT
TO MR. LURRY.
AUTHORIZE SHORE LEAVE
FOR ALL OFF-DUTY PERSONNEL.
YES, CAPTAIN.
KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
HOW DARE YOU AUTHORIZE
A MERE TWO MEN
FOR A PROJECT
OF THIS IMPORTANCE?
STARFLEET COMMAND WILL
HEAR ABOUT THIS.
I HAVE NEVER QUESTIONED
THE ORDERS
OR THE INTELLIGENCE
OF ANY REPRESENTATIVE
OF THE FEDERATION...
UNTIL NOW.
SUMMONING A STARSHIP
ON A PRIORITY A-1 CHANNEL
TO GUARD SOME
STORAGE COMPARTMENTS.
STORAGE COMPARTMENTS
OF WHEAT.
NEVERTHELESS,
CAPTAIN,
THE KLINGONS
WOULD NOT ENJOY
SEEING US
SUCCESSFULLY DEVELOP
SHERMAN'S PLANET.
I GUESS NOT.
I SEE YOU DIDN'T
WASTE ANY TIME
TAKING YOUR SHORE LEAVE.
HOW OFTEN DO I
GET SHORE LEAVE?
SHE WANTS TO SHOP,
AND I THOUGHT I
WOULD HELP HER.
OH, EXCUSE ME.
EXCUSE ME.
MR. CHEKOV, WHAT
DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
OH, QUADRO-TRITICALE.
I'VE READ ABOUT THIS,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANY BEFORE.
DOES EVERYBODY KNOW
ABOUT THIS WHEAT BUT ME?
WELL, NOT EVERYONE,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S A RUSSIAN INVENTION.
OH.
Man: I DON'T WANT ANY.
I TOLD YOU BEFORE,
AND I'M TELLING YOU AGAIN--
I DON'T WANT ANY MORE
SPIKE AND FLAME GEMS.
THANKS TO YOU,
I ALREADY HAVE ENOUGH
SPIKE AND FLAME GEMS
TO LAST ME A LIFETIME.
HOW SAD FOR YOU,
MY FRIEND.
YOU WON'T FIND
A FINER STONE
ANYWHERE.
BUT I HAVE
SOMETHING BETTER.
SURELY YOU WANT
SOME...
ANTARIAN GLOW WATER.
I USE THAT
TO POLISH THE FLAME GEMS.
YOU'RE A DIFFICULT
MAN TO REACH,
BUT I HAVE SOMETHING
FROM THE FAR REACHES
OF THE GALAXY.
SURELY YOU WANT--
NOT AT YOUR PRICE.
WHAT IS IT?
IS IT ALIVE?
MAY I HOLD IT?
OH, IT'S ADORABLE.
WHAT IS IT?
WHY, LOVELY LADY,
IT'S A TRIBBLE.
A TRIBBLE?
ONLY THE SWEETEST
CREATURE KNOWN TO MAN,
EXCEPTING, OF COURSE,
YOUR LOVELY SELF.
[PURRING]
OH, IT'S
PURRING.
LISTEN. IT'S PURRING.
IT'S ONLY SAYING
THAT IT LIKES YOU.
ARE YOU SELLING THEM?
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE TRYING
TO DECIDE RIGHT NOW.
MY FRIEND,
10 CREDITS APIECE
IS A VERY
REASONABLE PRICE.
NOW, YOU CAN SEE
FOR YOURSELF
HOW MUCH THE LOVELY
LITTLE LADY
APPRECIATES
THE FINER THINGS.
ONE CREDIT APIECE.
HE WON'T BITE, WILL HE?
SIR, TRANSPORTING
HARMFUL ANIMALS
FROM ONE PLANET
TO ANOTHER
IS AGAINST
REGULATIONS,
OR WEREN'T YOU
AWARE OF THAT?
BESIDES, TRIBBLES
HAVE NO TEETH.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL DOUBLE MY OFFER--
2 CREDITS.
TWICE NOTHING
IS STILL NOTHING.
WELL, IF YOU'RE NOT
GONNA TAKE HIM, I'M
GOING TO TAKE HIM.
I THINK HE'S CUTE.
4 CREDITS.
IS THAT AN OFFER
OR A JOKE?
THAT'S MY OFFER.
THAT'S A JOKE.
5?
I CAN SEE YOU'RE
AN HONEST MAN.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT
I'M GOING TO DO--
I'M GOING
TO LESSEN MY PRICE
TO 8 1/2 CREDITS.
YOU'RE TALKING YOURSELF
OUT OF A DEAL, FRIEND.
6 CREDITS.
NOT A CREDIT MORE.
7 1/2.
7?
ALL RIGHT,
YOU ROBBER.
6 CREDITS.
DONE. WHEN CAN I
HAVE THEM?
RIGHT AWAY.
WHAT ARE YOU
SELLING THEM FOR?
WELL, LET ME SEE,
LITTLE LADY.
SIX CREDITS. I FIGURE
A REASONABLE MARKUP
FOR A REASONABLE PROFIT--
SAY A 10% MARKUP--
10 CREDITS.
THIEF.
IN FACT, I'LL SELL YOU
THIS ONE.
HEY!
HE'S EATING MY GRAIN.
THAT'LL BE 10 CREDITS.
THAT HAPPENS
TO BE MY SAMPLE.
AND I'LL DO WITH IT
AS I PLEASE,
AND I PLEASE TO GIVE
IT TO THE LOVELY
LITTLE LADY HERE.
OH, I COULDN'T...
COULD I?
I INSIST.
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO DO,
RUIN THE MARKET?
Salesman: ONCE THIS
LOVELY LITTLE LADY
STARTS TO SHOW
THIS PRECIOUS LITTLE
DARLING AROUND,
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO
KEEP UP WITH THEM.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
YES, WHAT IS IT?
MESSAGE FROM
STARFLEET, CAPTAIN.
PRIORITY CHANNEL.
ADMIRAL FITZPATRICK
SPEAKING.
PUT IT ON VISUAL,
LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN KIRK?
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN,
IT IS NOT NECESSARY
TO REMIND YOU
OF THE IMPORTANCE
TO THE FEDERATION
OF SHERMAN'S
PLANET.
THE KEY
TO OUR WINNING
OF THIS PLANET
IS THE GRAIN
QUADRO-TRITICALE.
THE SHIPMENT OF IT
MUST BE PROTECTED.
EFFECTIVE
IMMEDIATELY,
YOU WILL RENDER ANY
AID AND ASSISTANCE
WHICH UNDERSECRETARY
BARIS MAY REQUIRE.
THE SAFETY
OF THE GRAIN
AND THE PROJECT
IS YOUR
RESPONSIBILITY.
STARFLEET OUT.
NOW, THAT'S JUST LOVELY.
BUT NOT TOTALLY
UNEXPECTED.
[INTERCOM WHISTLE]
CAPTAIN KIRK!
YES, LIEUTENANT,
WHAT IS IT?
SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
A KLINGON BATTLE CRUISER
RAPIDLY CLOSING
ON THE STATION.
GO TO RED ALERT.
NOTIFY MR. LURRY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT UP.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
WHAT IS THE POSITION
OF THE KLINGON SHIP?
100 KILOMETERS
OFF K-7.
IT'S JUST
SITTING THERE.
CAPTAIN,
I HAVE MR. LURRY.
PUT HIM ON VISUAL.
AYE, SIR.
MR. LURRY, THERE'S
A KLINGON WARSHIP
HANGING
100 KILOMETERS
OFF YOUR STATION.
I DON'T THINK
THE KLINGONS ARE
PLANNING TO ATTACK US.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE AT THIS MOMENT,
THE CAPTAIN
OF THE KLINGON SHIP
IS SITTING RIGHT HERE
IN MY OFFICE.
CANCEL RED ALERT.
WE'LL BEAM
RIGHT DOWN.
SECURITY,
CANCEL RED ALERT.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4524.2.
A KLINGON WARSHIP
IS HOVERING
ONLY 100 KILOMETERS
FROM DEEP
SPACE STATION K-7
WHILE ITS CAPTAIN WAITS
IN THE STATION MANAGER'S
OFFICE.
THEIR INTENTIONS
ARE UNKNOWN.
AH, MY DEAR CAPTAIN KIRK.
MY DEAR CAPTAIN KOLOTH.
LET ME ASSURE YOU THAT
MY INTENTIONS ARE PEACEFUL.
AS I'VE ALREADY TOLD
MR. LURRY,
THE PURPOSE
OF MY PRESENCE HERE
IS TO INVOKE
SHORE LEAVE RIGHTS.
SHORE LEAVE?
CAPTAIN, WE KLINGONS
ARE NOT AS LUXURY-MINDED
AS YOU EARTHERS.
WE DO NOT
EQUIP OUR SHIPS WITH--
HOW SHALL I SAY IT?
NONESSENTIALS.
WE HAVE BEEN IN SPACE
FOR FIVE MONTHS.
WHAT WE CHOOSE
AS RECREATION
IS OUR OWN BUSINESS.
I MIGHT ALSO ADD
THAT UNDER THE TERMS OF
THE ORGANIAN PEACE TREATY,
YOU CANNOT REFUSE US.
YES, WELL, I DON'T MAKE
THOSE DECISIONS.
MR. LURRY IS IN CHARGE
OF THOSE MATTERS.
CAPTAIN, MAY I
SPEAK TO YOU A MINUTE?
KIRK, I DON'T WANT
THEM HERE,
BUT I DON'T HAVE
THE AUTHORITY TO REFUSE.
WHILE I HAVE
THE AUTHORITY
TO ACT,
I'M GOING TO USE IT.
MY DEAR
CAPTAIN KOLOTH,
YOU MAY INDEED
BRING YOUR MEN
DOWN ON SHORE LEAVE,
BUT ONLY
12 AT A TIME.
AND I ASSURE YOU
THAT FOR EVERY MAN
YOU BRING DOWN HERE,
I SHALL HAVE
ONE SECURITY GUARD.
THERE WILL BE
NO TROUBLE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THERE'S BEEN NO FORMAL
DECLARATION OF HOSTILITIES
BETWEEN OUR TWO
RESPECTIVE GOVERNMENTS,
SO NATURALLY
OUR RELATIONSHIP
WILL BE A PEACEFUL ONE.
LET US BOTH TAKE STEPS
TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
OF COURSE.
ANOTHER TECHNICAL
JOURNAL, SCOTTY?
AYE.
DON'T YOU EVER RELAX?
WELL,
I AM RELAXING.
[PURRING]
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
HAD THAT THING,
LIEUTENANT?
SINCE YESTERDAY,
DOCTOR.
THIS MORNING, I
FOUND OUT THAT HE--
I MEAN SHE
HAD HAD BABIES.
WELL, I'D SAY IN THAT
CASE, YOU GOT A BARGAIN.
YOU RUNNING
A NURSERY,
LIEUTENANT?
OH, CAPTAIN.
WELL, I HADN'T
INTENDED TO, SIR,
BUT THE TRIBBLE
HAD OTHER PLANS.
DID YOU GET THIS
AT THE SPACE STATION?
YES, SIR.
A MOST CURIOUS
CREATURE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S TRILLING SEEMS TO HAVE
A TRANQUILIZING EFFECT
ON THE HUMAN
NERVOUS SYSTEM.
FORTUNATELY, OF COURSE,
I AM...IMMUNE
[SOFTLY]
TO ITS EFFECT.
LIEUTENANT, DO YOU MIND
IF I TAKE ONE OF THESE
DOWN TO THE LAB
AND SEE WHAT MAKES IT TICK?
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
DOCTOR,
BUT IF YOU'RE
GOING TO DISSECT IT,
I DON'T WANT
TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
I WON'T HARM
A HAIR ON ITS HEAD--
WHEREVER THAT IS.
SAY, LIEUTENANT,
SEEING AS YOU'RE
GIVING THEM AWAY,
CAN I HAVE ONE?
WELL, SURE. WHY NOT?
I THINK
THEY'RE OLD ENOUGH.
GO AHEAD.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
MR. BARIS IS WAITING
ON CHANNEL "E"
TO SPEAK TO YOU, SIR.
PIPE IT DOWN HERE,
WILL YOU, MR. CHEKOV.
AYE, SIR.
MR. BARIS IS COMING ON.
YES, MR. BARIS,
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
KIRK, THIS STATION
IS SWARMING WITH KLINGONS.
I WAS NOT AWARE,
MR. BARIS,
THAT 12 KLINGONS
CONSTITUTES A SWARM.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THERE ARE KLINGON SOLDIERS
ON THIS STATION.
NOW, I WANT YOU
TO KEEP THAT GRAIN SAFE.
MR. BARIS, I HAVE GUARDS
AROUND THE GRAIN.
I HAVE GUARDS
AROUND
THE KLINGONS.
THE ONLY REASON
THOSE GUARDS ARE THERE
IS BECAUSE STARFLEET
WANTS THEM THERE.
AS FOR WHAT YOU WANT...
IT HAS BEEN NOTED
AND LOGGED. KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN, MAY I ASK
WHERE YOU'LL BE?
SICK BAY WITH A HEADACHE.
HI, JIM.
BONES, WHAT DO YOU GOT
FOR A HEADACHE?
LET ME GUESS.
THE KLINGONS? BARIS?
BOTH. HOW MANY OF THESE
DID UHURA GIVE YOU?
JUST ONE.
BUT YOU'VE GOT, UH, 11.
YOU NOTICED
THAT, HUH?
HERE. THIS OUGHT TO
TAKE CARE OF IT.
HOW DO THEY...
I HAVEN'T FIGURED
THAT OUT YET,
BUT I CAN TELL YOU
THIS MUCH--
ALMOST 50%
OF THE CREATURE'S
METABOLISM
IS GEARED
FOR REPRODUCTION.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU GET
IF YOU FEED
A TRIBBLE TOO MUCH?
A FAT TRIBBLE.
NO. YOU GET
A WHOLE BUNCH
OF HUNGRY LITTLE
TRIBBLES.
WELL, BONES,
ALL I CAN SUGGEST...
IS YOU OPEN UP
A MATERNITY WARD.
I WANT ALL YOU MEN
WHO ARE GOING ON SHORE
LEAVE TO STAY IN GROUPS.
AVOID TROUBLE
WITH THE KLINGONS.
I'LL TELL THEM
BEFORE THEY GO, SIR.
AREN'T YOU GOING
ON SHORE LEAVE, SCOTTY?
WHY, NO, SIR.
I WANT YOU TO GO
ON SHORE LEAVE.
MAKE SURE THAT EVERYBODY
STAYS OUT OF TROUBLE.
BUT, CAPTAIN...
AYE, SIR.
SCOTTY, ENJOY YOURSELF.
[WHISTLING]
AH, FRIENDS,
CAN I OFFER YOU
A CHARMING
LITTLE TRIBBLE?
UH, NO, THANKS.
OH. PERHAPS ONE
OF YOU OTHER GENTS?
EH.
AH, FRIEND KLINGON.
[SHRIEKING]
COULD I INTEREST
YOU IN A HARMLESS
LITTLE TRIBBLE?
GET IT AWAY FROM ME.
I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THEM
ACT THIS WAY BEFORE.
GET OUT OF HERE
WITH THAT PARASITE.
HE'S ONLY
A HARMLESS LITTLE--
TAKE IT AWAY!
YES.
[SHRIEKING]
AH, MY GOOD FRIEND.
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE
TO ENTER ANOTHER
LITTLE TRANSACTION?
THIS TIME,
A TRIBBLE
FOR A SPOT--
A TRIBBLE.
A TRIBBLE?
EH, EH...
A TRIBBLE.
WHEN ARE YOU GONNA
GET OFF THAT MILK DIET, LAD?
THIS IS VODKA.
WHERE I COME FROM,
THAT'S SODA POP.
NOW, THIS IS A DRINK
FOR A MAN.
SCOTCH?
AYE.
IT WAS INVENTED BY
A LITTLE OLD LADY
FROM LENINGRAD.
[SHRIEKING]
THE EARTHERS
LIKE THOSE FUZZY THINGS,
DON'T THEY?
OH, YES.
WELL, FRANKLY,
I NEVER LIKED EARTHERS.
THEY REMIND ME
OF REGULAN BLOODWORMS.
[KLINGONS LAUGHING]
THAT COSSACK.
EASY, LAD.
YOU OUGHT TO BE
MORE FORGIVING.
OH.
I JUST REMEMBERED.
THERE IS ONE EARTH MAN
WHO DOESN'T REMIND ME
OF A REGULAN BLOODWORM.
THAT'S KIRK.
A REGULAN BLOODWORM
IS SOFT AND SHAPELESS,
BUT KIRK
ISN'T SOFT.
KIRK MAY BE
A SWAGGERING,
OVERBEARING,
TIN-PLATED DICTATOR
WITH DELUSIONS
OF GODHOOD,
BUT HE'S NOT SOFT.
TAKE IT EASY, LAD.
EVERYBODY'S ENTITLED
TO AN OPINION.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IF I THINK THAT KIRK
IS A DENIBIAN SLIME DEVIL,
WELL, THAT'S
MY OPINION, TOO.
DON'T DO IT, MISTER,
AND THAT'S AN ORDER.
BUT YOU HEARD
WHAT HE CALLED
THE CAPTAIN.
FORGET IT.
IT'S NOT WORTH
FIGHTING FOR.
WE'RE BIG ENOUGH
TO TAKE A FEW INSULTS.
NOW, DRINK YOUR DRINK.
OF COURSE,
I'D SAY THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
DESERVES HIS SHIP.
WE LIKE THE "ENTERPRISE."
WE--WE REALLY DO.
THAT SAGGING
OLD RUST BUCKET
IS DESIGNED
LIKE A GARBAGE SCOW.
HALF THE QUADRANT
KNOWS IT.
THAT'S WHY THEY'RE LEARNING
TO SPEAK KLINGONI.
MR. SCOTT.
LADDIE, DON'T YOU THINK
YOU SHOULD...
REPHRASE THAT?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I SHOULD.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO SAY
THAT THE "ENTERPRISE"
SHOULD BE HAULING GARBAGE.
I MEANT TO SAY
THAT IT
SHOULD BE HAULED AWAY
AS GARBAGE.
[KLINGON LAUGHING]
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 4525.6.
A SMALL DISTURBANCE
BETWEEN THE KLINGON CREW
AND MEMBERS
OF THE "ENTERPRISE" CREW
HAS BROKEN OUT ABOARD
SPACE STATION K-7.
I AM FORCED
TO CANCEL SHORE LEAVE
FOR BOTH SHIPS.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHO STARTED IT.
I'M WAITING.
FREEMAN, WHO STARTED
THE FIGHT?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
CHEKOV.
I KNOW YOU.
YOU STARTED IT,
DIDN'T YOU?
NO, SIR, I DIDN'T.
WELL, WHO DID?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
"I DON'T KNOW, SIR."
I WANT
TO KNOW WHO THREW
THE FIRST PUNCH.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE ALL CONFINED
TO QUARTERS
UNTIL I FIND OUT
WHO STARTED IT.
DISMISSED.
SCOTTY, NOT YOU.
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO PREVENT TROUBLE,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
WHO THREW
THE FIRST PUNCH, SCOTTY?
UM...
SCOTTY.
I DID, CAPTAIN.
YOU DID, MR. SCOTT?
WHAT CAUSED IT, SCOTTY?
THEY INSULTED
US, SIR.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
SOME INSULT.
AYE, IT WAS.
YOU THREW
THE FIRST PUNCH.
AYE.
CHEKOV WANTED TO,
BUT I HELD HIM BACK.
YOU HELD--
WHY DID CHEKOV
WANT TO START A FIGHT?
UM...WELL,
THE KLINGONS, SIR...
IS THIS
OFF THE RECORD?
NO. THIS IS NOT
OFF THE RECORD.
WELL, CAPTAIN, UH...
THE KLINGONS
CALLED YOU, UH...
A TIN-PLATED,
OVERBEARING,
SWAGGERING DICTATOR
WITH DELUSIONS
OF GODHOOD.
IS THAT ALL?
NO, SIR.
THEY ALSO COMPARED YOU
WITH A DENIBIAN
SLIME DEVIL.
I SEE.
AND THEN THEY SAID
THAT YOU WERE A--
I GET THE PICTURE, SCOTTY.
YES, SIR.
AND AFTER THEY SAID
ALL THIS,
THAT'S WHEN YOU HIT
THE KLINGONS?
NO, SIR.
NO?
NO, UH...I DIDN'T.
YOU TOLD US
TO AVOID TROUBLE.
OH, YES.
AND I DIDN'T SEE
THAT IT WAS WORTH
FIGHTING ABOUT.
AFTER ALL, WE'RE
BIG ENOUGH TO TAKE
A FEW INSULTS.
AREN'T WE?
WHAT WAS IT THEY SAID
THAT STARTED THE FIGHT?
THEY CALLED
THE "ENTERPRISE"
A GARBAGE SCOW...
SIR.
I SEE.
AND...
THAT'S WHEN YOU HIT
THE KLINGONS?
YES, SIR.
YOU HIT THE KLINGONS
BECAUSE THEY INSULTED
THE "ENTERPRISE,"
NOT BECAUSE THEY...
WELL, SIR, THIS WAS
A MATTER OF PRIDE.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
DISMISSED.
OH...
SCOTTY, YOU'RE
RESTRICTED TO QUARTERS
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
YES, SIR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THAT'LL
GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO CATCH UP ON MY
TECHNICAL JOURNALS.
[PURRING]
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
SPOCK?
THERE'S SOMETHING
DISQUIETING ABOUT
THESE CREATURES.
OH? DON'T TELL
ME YOU'VE
GOT A FEELING.
DON'T BE INSULTING,
DOCTOR.
THEY REMIND ME
OF THE LILIES
OF THE FIELD.
"THEY TOIL NOT,
NEITHER DO THEY SPIN."
BUT THEY SEEM TO EAT
A GREAT DEAL.
I SEE NO PRACTICAL
USE FOR THEM.
DOES EVERYTHING
HAVE TO HAVE
A PRACTICAL USE
FOR YOU?
THEY'RE NICE,
THEY'RE SOFT,
AND THEY'RE FURRY,
AND THEY MAKE
A PLEASANT SOUND.
SO WOULD
AN ERMINE VIOLIN, DOCTOR,
BUT I SEE NO ADVANTAGE
IN HAVING ONE.
IT IS A HUMAN
CHARACTERISTIC TO
LOVE LITTLE ANIMALS,
ESPECIALLY IF
THEY'RE ATTRACTIVE
IN SOME WAY.
DOCTOR, I AM WELL AWARE
OF HUMAN CHARACTERISTICS.
I AM FREQUENTLY
INUNDATED BY THEM,
BUT I HAVE TRAINED MYSELF
TO PUT UP WITH
PRACTICALLY ANYTHING.
SPOCK, I DON'T KNOW
TOO MUCH ABOUT THESE
LITTLE TRIBBLES YET,
BUT THERE IS
ONE THING THAT
I HAVE DISCOVERED.
WHAT IS THAT, DOCTOR?
I LIKE THEM...
BETTER THAN
I LIKE YOU.
DOCTOR?
YES?
THEY DO INDEED HAVE ONE
REDEEMING CHARACTERISTIC.
WHAT'S THAT?
THEY DO NOT TALK TOO MUCH.
IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
[SHRIEK]
DR. McCOY, WOULD YOU MIND
COMING UP TO THE BRIDGE?
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HOW DID ALL THESE TRIBBLES
GET ON THE BRIDGE?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
THEY DO SEEM TO BE
ALL OVER THE SHIP.
DR. McCOY.
YES? DID YOU WANT
TO SEE ME, JIM?
WELL,
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
IT'S THE TRIBBLES
WHO ARE BREEDING.
IF WE DON'T GET
THEM OFF THIS SHIP,
WE'RE GOING TO BE
HIP DEEP IN THEM.
WOULD YOU EXPLAIN THAT?
WELL,
THE NEAREST THING
I CAN FIGURE OUT
IS THAT THEY'RE
BORN PREGNANT,
WHICH SEEMS TO BE
QUITE A TIMESAVER.
I KNOW, BUT REALLY...
AND FROM
MY OBSERVATIONS,
IT SEEMS
THEY'RE BISEXUAL,
REPRODUCING AT WILL.
AND, BROTHER,
HAVE THEY GOT
A LOT OF WILL.
CAPTAIN, I'M FORCED
TO AGREE WITH THE DOCTOR.
I'VE BEEN RUNNING
COMPUTATIONS ON THEIR
RATE OF REPRODUCTION.
THE FIGURES ARE TAKING
AN ALARMING DIRECTION.
THEY'RE CONSUMING
OUR SUPPLIES
AND RETURNING NOTHING.
OH, BUT THEY DO
GIVE US SOMETHING,
MR. SPOCK.
THEY GIVE US LOVE.
WELL, CYRANO JONES
SAYS THAT A TRIBBLE
IS THE ONLY LOVE
THAT MONEY CAN BUY.
TOO MUCH OF ANYTHING,
LIEUTENANT, EVEN LOVE,
ISN'T NECESSARILY
A GOOD THING.
[SHRIEKING]
YES, CAPTAIN.
HAVE MAINTENANCE CREW CLEAN UP
THE ENTIRE SHIP,
AND THEN...
CONTACT MR. LURRY
AND TELL HIM
I'M BEAMING DOWN.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
HAVE HIM FIND
CYRANO JONES
AND HOLD HIM.
AYE.
AND GET THESE TRIBBLES
OFF THE BRIDGE.
AYE-AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I'M MYSTIFIED
AT YOUR TONE OF VOICE.
I'VE DONE NOTHING TO WARRANT
SUCH SEVERE TREATMENT.
OH, REALLY?
SURELY YOU MUST HAVE
REALIZED WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF YOU REMOVED
THE TRIBBLES
FROM THEIR PREDATOR-FILLED
ENVIRONMENT
INTO AN ENVIRONMENT
WHERE THEIR NATURAL
MULTIPLICATIVE PROCLIVITIES
WOULD HAVE
NO RESTRAINING FACTORS.
WELL, OF COUR--
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
BY REMOVING THE TRIBBLES
FROM THEIR NATURAL HABITAT,
YOU HAVE, SO TO SPEAK,
REMOVED THE CORK
FROM THE BOTTLE
AND ALLOWED
THE GENIE TO ESCAPE.
IF BY THAT YOU MEAN
DO THEY BREED QUICKLY?
WELL, OF COURSE.
THAT'S HOW I
MAINTAIN MY STOCK.
BREEDING ANIMALS IS NOT
AGAINST REGULATIONS,
ONLY BREEDING
DANGEROUS ONES,
AND TRIBBLES
ARE NOT DANGEROUS.
JUST INCREDIBLY
PROLIFIC.
PRECISELY, AND AT
6 CREDITS A HEAD--
UH, WELL,
THAT IS, A BODY,
IT MOUNTS UP. NOW
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME.
YOU SHOULD
SELL AN INSTRUCTION
AND MAINTENANCE MANUAL
WITH THIS THING.
IF I DID,
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
TO MAN'S SEARCH
FOR KNOWLEDGE?
WELL, I MUST BE
TENDING MY SHIP.
AU REVOIR.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
TELL HIM.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I CONSIDER YOUR SECURITY
MEASURES A DISGRACE.
IN MY OPINION,
YOU HAVE TAKEN
THIS ENTIRE VERY
IMPORTANT PROJECT
FAR TOO LIGHTLY.
ON THE CONTRARY, SIR.
I THINK OF THIS PROJECT
AS VERY IMPORTANT.
IT IS YOU
I TAKE LIGHTLY.
I AM GOING
TO REPORT FULLY
TO THE PROPER
AUTHORITIES
THAT YOU HAVE GIVEN
FREE AND COMPLETE ACCESS
TO THIS STATION
TO A MAN WHO IS QUITE
PROBABLY A KLINGON AGENT.
NOW, THAT'S
A VERY SERIOUS CHARGE.
TO WHOM ARE YOU REFERRING?
TO THAT MAN WHO JUST
WALKED OUT OF HERE.
CYRANO JONES?
A KLINGON AGENT?
YOU HEARD ME.
I HEARD YOU.
HE SIMPLY COULD NOT
BELIEVE HIS EARS.
WHAT EVIDENCE
DO YOU HAVE
AGAINST MR. JONES?
MY ASSISTANT HERE
HAS KEPT MR. JONES
UNDER CLOSE SURVEILLANCE
FOR QUITE SOME TIME,
AND HIS ACTIONS HAVE
BEEN MOST SUSPICIOUS.
I BELIEVE HE WAS
INVOLVED IN THAT
LITTLE ALTERCATION
BETWEEN YOUR MAN
AND THE MAN
FROM HIS SHIP--
YES, YES. GO ON.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU HAVE?
WELL, CAPTAIN,
I CHECKED
HIS SHIP'S LOG.
AND IT SEEMS
THAT HE WAS WITHIN
THE KLINGONS'
SPHERE OF
INFLUENCE LESS THAN
FOUR MONTHS AGO.
THE MAN IS
AN INDEPENDENT
SCOUT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S QUITE POSSIBLE THAT
HE IS ALSO A KLINGON SPY.
WE HAVE ALREADY CHECKED
ON THE BACKGROUND
OF MR. CYRANO JONES.
HE IS A LICENSED
ASTEROID LOCATOR
AND PROSPECTOR.
HE'S NEVER
BROKEN THE LAW,
AT LEAST NOT SEVERELY.
AND FOR THE PAST
SEVEN YEARS
WITH HIS
ONE-MAN SPACESHIP,
HE HAS OBTAINED
A MARGINAL LIVING
BY ENGAGING IN
THE BUYING AND SELLING
OF RARE MERCHANDISE,
INCLUDING,
UNFORTUNATELY, TRIBBLES.
BUT HE IS AFTER MY GRAIN!
DO YOU HAVE
ANY PROOF OF THAT?
YOU CAN'T DENY
HE'S DISRUPTED
THIS STATION.
PEOPLE HAVE DISRUPTED
STATIONS BEFORE
WITHOUT BEING
KLINGON AGENTS.
SOMETIMES, ALL THEY NEED
IS A TITLE, MR. BARIS.
UNFORTUNATELY, DISRUPTING
A SPACE STATION
IS NOT AN OFFENSE.
NOW, IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME,
I HAVE A SHIP
TO TEND TO. AU REVOIR.
MY CHICKEN SANDWICH
AND COFFEE.
THIS IS MY CHICKEN
SANDWICH AND COFFEE.
FASCINATING.
I WANT THESE THINGS
OFF THE SHIP.
I DON'T CARE IF IT TAKES
EVERY MAN WE'VE GOT.
I WANT THEM OFF THE SHIP.
AYE. THEY'RE INTO
THE MACHINERY, ALL
RIGHT. AND THEY'RE
PROBABLY IN
ALL THE OTHER FOOD
PROCESSORS, TOO.
HOW?
PROBABLY THROUGH ONE
OF THE AIR VENTS.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE
VENTS OF THAT TYPE
ON THE SPACE STATION.
AND IN THE STORAGE
COMPARTMENTS.
THIS IS KIRK.
CONTACT MANAGER LURRY
AND NILZ BARIS.
HAVE THEM MEET US NEAR
THE STORAGE COMPARTMENTS.
WE'RE BEAMING DOWN.
COME ON, SPOCK.
ENERGIZE.
[SHRIEKING]
WHAT'S WRONG?
PLENTY, IF WHAT
I THINK HAPPENED
HAS HAPPENED.
GUARD,
IS THAT DOOR SECURE?
YES, SIR.
NOTHING COULD GET IN.
GOOD. OPEN IT.
IT'S NOT WORKING, SIR.
IT SEEMS TO BE STUCK.
HERE. LET ME TRY IT.
THEY SEEM
TO BE GORGED.
GORGED? ON MY GRAIN?
KIRK, I AM GOING
TO HOLD YOU RESPONSIBLE.
THERE MUST BE
THOUSANDS OF THEM.
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS.
1,771,561.
THAT'S ASSUMING
ONE TRIBBLE,
MULTIPLYING
WITH AN AVERAGE
LITTER OF 10,
PRODUCING
A NEW GENERATION
EVERY 12 HOURS
OVER A PERIOD
OF THREE DAYS.
AND THAT'S
ASSUMING THAT THEY GOT
HERE THREE DAYS AGO.
AND ALLOWING FOR
THE AMOUNT OF
GRAIN CONSUMED
AND THE VOLUME
OF THE STORAGE
COMPARTMENT.
KIRK, YOU SHOULD
HAVE KNOWN.
YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR TURNING
THE DEVELOPMENT PROJECT
INTO A TOTAL DISASTER.
MR. BARIS--
AND I'M THROUGH BEING
INTIMIDATED, KIRK.
NOW, YOU HAVE INSULTED ME,
YOU HAVE IGNORED ME,
YOU'VE WALKED
ALL OVER ME.
YOU HAVE ABUSED
YOUR AUTHORITY,
AND YOU HAVE REJECTED
MY REQUESTS.
AND THIS--
THIS IS THE RESULT.
I AM GOING TO HOLD
YOU RESPONSIBLE, KIRK.
MR. BARIS,
I'LL HOLD YOU IN IRONS
IF YOU DON'T SHUT UP.
JIM, I THINK
I'VE GOT IT.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO IS
QUIT FEEDING THEM.
IF WE QUIT
FEEDING THEM,
THEY STOP BREEDING.
NOW HE TELLS ME.
CAPTAIN...
THIS TRIBBLE
IS DEAD.
AND SO ARE THESE.
A LOT OF THEM ARE DEAD.
A LOT OF THEM
ARE ALIVE.
THEY WON'T BE FOR LONG.
THE LOGICAL ASSUMPTION
IS THAT THERE IS
SOMETHING IN THE GRAIN.
YES. BONES,
I WANT THE TRIBBLES,
THE GRAIN,
EVERYTHING ANALYZED.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT
KILLED THESE TRIBBLES.
I HAVEN'T FIGURED OUT
WHAT KEEPS THEM ALIVE YET.
ALL RIGHT.
IF I FIND OUT ANYTHING,
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
THAT ISN'T GOING TO DO
YOU ANY GOOD, KIRK.
THIS PROJECT IS RUINED,
AND STARFLEET IS GOING
TO HEAR ABOUT IT.
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THEY WILL HAVE
A BOARD OF INQUIRY.
AND THEY WILL
ROAST YOU ALIVE.
YES, WELL--
AND I AM GOING
TO BE THERE,
KIRK, TO ENJOY
EVERY MINUTE OF IT.
YES. UNTIL THAT
BOARD OF INQUIRY,
I'M STILL THE CAPTAIN.
AND AS CAPTAIN,
I WANT TWO THINGS DONE.
FIRST, FIND CYRANO JONES,
AND SECOND...
CLOSE THAT DOOR.
REALLY, CAPTAIN KIRK,
I MUST PROTEST
THIS TREATMENT.
AH, MR. JONES,
WITH AN ARMFUL.
A FEW QUESTIONS.
CAPTAIN KIRK!
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
AN OFFICIAL APOLOGY
ADDRESSED
TO THE KLINGON
HIGH COMMAND.
I EXPECT YOU TO ASSUME
FULL RESPONSIBILITY
FOR THE PERSECUTION
OF KLINGON NATIONALS
IN THIS QUADRANT.
AN APOLOGY?
YES. YOU'VE HARASSED
MY MEN.
YOU'VE TREATED THEM
LIKE CRIMINALS.
YOU'VE BEEN
MOST UNCOURTEOUS,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
NOW, IF YOU WISH TO
AVOID A DIPLOMATIC
INCIDENT--
NO, KIRK.
YOU CAN'T LET HIM.
THAT WILL GIVE THEM
THE WEDGE THEY NEED
TO CLAIM
SHERMAN'S PLANET.
I BELIEVE THAT MORE THAN
THE WORD OF AN AGGRIEVED
KLINGON COMMANDER
WOULD BE NECESSARY
FOR THAT, MR. BARIS.
MR. SPOCK,
AS FAR AS SHERMAN'S
PLANET IS CONCERNED,
CAPTAIN KIRK HAS ALREADY
GIVEN IT TO US.
WELL, WE'LL SEE
ABOUT THAT,
BUT BEFORE I TAKE
ANY OFFICIAL ACTION,
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
JUST WHAT HAPPENED.
WHO PUT THE TRIBBLES
IN THE QUADRO-TRITICALE?
AND WHAT WAS
IN THE GRAIN
THAT KILLED THEM?
CAPTAIN KIRK,
BEFORE YOU GO ON,
MAY I MAKE A REQUEST?
YES.
CAN YOU GET THOSE
THINGS OUT OF HERE?
[SHRIEKING]
REMARKABLE.
HOLD ON A MINUTE.
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
TRIBBLES LIKED EVERYBODY.
WELL, THEY DO. I
CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
THE LAST TIME I SAW
ONE ACT THIS WAY
WAS AT THE BAR.
WHAT WAS IN THE BAR?
KLINGONS.
HIM, FOR ONE.
[SHRIEKING]
WHY, YOU'RE
RIGHT,
MR. JONES.
THEY DON'T
LIKE KLINGONS.
[SHRIEKING]
BUT THEY DO
LIKE VULCANS.
[PURRING]
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU HAD IT IN YOU.
OBVIOUSLY TRIBBLES
ARE VERY PERCEPTIVE
CREATURES, CAPTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY.
[PURRING]
MR. BARIS,
THEY LIKE YOU.
WELL, THERE'S
NO ACCOUNTING
FOR TASTE.
[SHRIEKING]
THEY DON'T LIKE YOU,
MR. DARVIN. I WONDER WHY.
BONES?
HEARTBEAT IS ALL WRONG.
HIS BODY TEMPERATURE IS--
JIM, THIS MAN
IS A KLINGON.
A KLINGON?
I WONDER WHAT
STARFLEET COMMAND
WILL SAY ABOUT THAT.
WHAT ABOUT
THE GRAIN, BONES?
OH, YES.
IT WAS POISONED.
POISONED?
YES. IT'S BEEN
IMPREGNATED
WITH A VIRUS.
THE VIRUS TURNS
INTO AN INERT
MATERIAL
IN THE BLOODSTREAM.
THE MORE
THE ORGANISM EATS,
INERT MATTER
IS BUILT UP.
SO AFTER
TWO OR 3 DAYS, IT
WOULD REACH A POINT
TO WHERE THEY
COULDN'T TAKE IN
ENOUGH NOURISHMENT
TO SURVIVE.
THEY STARVED TO DEATH.
IN A STORAGE COMPARTMENT
FULL OF GRAIN,
THEY STARVED TO DEATH.
THAT IS
ESSENTIALLY IT.
[SHRIEKING]
MR. DARVIN,
YOU GOING TO TALK?
I HAVE
NOTHING TO SAY.
ALL RIGHT!
I POISONED
THE GRAIN!
TAKE THEM AWAY.
AND THE TRIBBLES HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH IT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I NEVER SAW
ONE BEFORE
IN MY LIFE,
AND I HOPE
I NEVER SEE
ONE OF THOSE
FUZZY MISERABLE
THINGS AGAIN.
I'M CERTAIN THAT
CAN BE ARRANGED, DARVIN.
GUARDS.
IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KOLOTH...
ABOUT THAT APOLOGY.
YES?
YOU HAVE SIX HOURS
TO GET YOUR SHIP
OUT OF FEDERATION
TERRITORY.
[SHRIEKING]
NO. NO...
[PURRING]
HEY, YOU KNOW, I THINK I COULD
LEARN TO LIKE TRIBBLES.
WELL, CAPTAIN, I SUPPOSE
I'M FREE TO GO NOW.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
EH?
THERE'S SOMETHING
I WANT TO SHOW YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THE PENALTY IS
FOR TRANSPORTING
AN ANIMAL
PROVEN HARMFUL
TO HUMAN LIFE?
CAPTAIN, ONE LITTLE
TRIBBLE ISN'T HARMFUL.
CAPTAIN, YOU WOULDN'T DO
A THING LIKE THAT TO ME,
NOW, WOULD YOU?
WOULD YOU?
THE PENALTY
IS 20 YEARS
IN A REHABILITATION
COLONY.
CAPTAIN KIRK--
FRIEND, FRIEND KIRK,
SURELY WE CAN COME
TO SOME SORT OF MUTUAL
UNDERSTANDING. HEH HEH.
AFTER ALL, MY TRIBBLES
DID PUT YOU WISE
TO THE POISONED GRAIN,
AND THEY DID HELP YOU
TO FIND THE KLINGON AGENT.
WE'VE SAVED A LOT
OF LIVES THAT WAY.
HMM?
THERE IS ONE THING
YOU CAN DO.
YES?
PICK UP EVERY TRIBBLE
ON THE SPACE STATION.
IF YOU DO THAT,
I'LL SPEAK TO MR. LURRY
ABOUT RETURNING
YOUR SPACESHIP.
THAT WOULD TAKE YEARS.
17.9 TO BE EXACT.
17.9 YEARS.
CONSIDER IT
JOB SECURITY.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE A HARD MAN.
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT!
YOU'LL DO IT?
I'LL DO IT.
CAPTAIN, STARFLEET
WAS ABLE TO DIVERT
THAT FREIGHTER.
GOOD. THAT MEANS
SHERMAN'S PLANET
WILL GET ITS
QUADRO-TRITICALE
ONLY A FEW WEEKS LATE.
I DON'T SEE
ANY TRIBBLES AROUND HERE.
McCoy: AND YOU WON'T
FIND A TRIBBLE
ON THIS ENTIRE SHIP.
BONES, HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
WELL, I CANNOT
TAKE CREDIT FOR
ANOTHER MAN'S WORK.
SCOTTY DID IT.
SCOTTY!
WHERE ARE THE TRIBBLES?
OH, UM, CAPTAIN,
IT WAS REALLY
MR. SPOCK'S
RECOMMENDATION.
OF COURSE. SPOCK.
BASED ON COMPUTER
ANALYSIS, OF COURSE,
TAKING INTO ACCOUNT
THE POSSIBILITIES OF--
GENTLEMEN, I DON'T
WANT TO INTERRUPT
THIS MUTUAL
ADMIRATION SOCIETY,
BUT I'D LIKE TO KNOW
WHERE THE TRIBBLES ARE.
TELL HIM, SPOCK.
WELL, IT WAS MR. SCOTT
WHO PERFORMED
THE ACTUAL ENGINEERING.
MR. SCOTT.
WHERE ARE THE TRIBBLES?
I USED
THE TRANSPORTER,
CAPTAIN.
YOU USED THE TRANSPORTER?
AYE.
WELL, WHERE DID YOU
TRANSPORT THEM?
SCOTT, YOU DIDN'T TRANSPORT
THEM INTO SPACE, DID YOU?
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THAT WOULD
BE INHUMAN.
WELL, WHERE ARE THEY?
I GAVE THEM A VERY
GOOD HOME, SIR.
WHERE?!
I GAVE THEM TO
THE KLINGONS, SIR.
YOU GAVE THEM
TO THE KLINGONS?
AYE, SIR.
BEFORE THEY
WENT INTO WARP,
I TRANSPORTED
THE WHOLE KIT AND
CABOODLE INTO
THEIR ENGINE ROOM,
WHERE THEY'LL BE
NO TRIBBLE AT ALL.
[LAUGHTER]