Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3211.7.
WE ARE ENTERING
STANDARD ORBIT
ABOUT GAMMA 2,
AN UNINHABITED
PLANETOID
WITH AN AUTOMATIC
COMMUNICATIONS
AND ASTROGATION STATION.
ENSIGN CHEKOV,
LIEUTENANT UHURA, AND I
WILL BEAM DOWN
AND MAKE A ROUTINE CHECK
OF ITS FACILITIES.
STANDARD ORBIT,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
MIND THE STORE,
MR. SPOCK.
ACKNOWLEDGED,
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
LET'S GO.
YES, SIR.
ENERGIZE, SCOTTY.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN...
WHAT HAPPENED?
MUST BE A...
TRANSPORTER
MALFUNCTION.
IT...WAS
A ROUGH TRIP.
THIS ISN'T GAMMA 2.
LOOK AT THE COLOR
OF THAT SKY.
THIS IS THE CRAZIEST
LANDING PAD
I'VE EVER SEEN.
THAT'S A TRINARY SUN.
SCOTT TO BRIDGE.
SPOCK HERE.
MR. SPOCK,
THE CAPTAIN,
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
AND CHEKOV...
THEY VANISHED.
THEY GOT ONTO
THE TRANSPORTER PLATFORM
AND THEY JUST VANISHED.
I PRESUME YOU MEAN
THEY VANISHED IN A MANNER
NOT CONSISTENT
WITH THE USUAL WORKINGS
OF THE TRANSPORTER,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE, OF COURSE
I MEAN THAT.
YOU THINK I'D CALL YOU
IF THEY JUST BEAMED DOWN?
HAVE YOU REVERSED CONTROLS?
I'VE MADE ALL
THE PROPER CHECKS.
THERE WAS NOTHING.
THERE WAS NO FLASH
OF LIGHT, NOTHING.
THEY WERE GONE.
POWER SURGE?
NOT DOWN HERE.
ALL THE DIALS WERE RIGHT
AND THE TRANSPORTER
WAS FUNCTIONING PERFECTLY.
RECHECK YOUR EQUIPMENT,
MR. SCOTT.
I'LL SCAN FOR THEM
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
SPOCK OUT.
BUT, CAPTAIN,
IF WE'RE NOT
ON GAMMA 2,
THEN WHERE ARE WE?
THAT'S WHAT
I'D LIKE TO KNOW.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
DEAD.
MINE, TOO.
CAPTAIN...
LOOK.
PHASERS...ON STUN.
FIRE.
HAND-TO-HAND.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3211.8.
WHILE BEAMING DOWN
FROM THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO INSPECT FACILITIES
ON GAMMA 2,
THE NORMAL
TRANSPORTER SEQUENCE
HAS BEEN INTERRUPTED,
AND WE FIND OURSELVES
ON A STRANGE
AND HOSTILE PLANET,
SURROUNDED BY CREATURES
BELONGING TO RACES
SCATTERED ALL THROUGH
THE GALAXY.
EXCELLENT,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
ALTHOUGH
WE EXPECTED STRENGTH
AND COMPETITIVE SPIRIT,
WE ARE GREATLY PLEASED.
EITHER OF YOU HURT?
I DON'T THINK
SO, CAPTAIN.
NOBODY'S HURT, CAPTAIN.
YET.
ADMIRABLE, CHEKOV.
ADMIRABLE.
YOU ALSO, UHURA.
YOUR SPIRIT
IS AS GREAT
AS THE CAPTAIN'S.
I CAN SEE
YOU WILL ALL PROVE
INVALUABLE HERE.
I AM GALT,
MASTER THRALL
OF THE PLANET
TRISKELION.
I HAVE BEEN SENT
TO WELCOME YOU.
THERE, CAPTAIN.
NOW YOU ARE PREPARED
FOR YOUR TRAINING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
OUR NAMES?
THE PROVIDERS
WERE EXPECTING YOU,
CAPTAIN.
THEY ARRANGED
YOUR TRANSPORTATION.
THESE PROVIDERS
OF YOURS, ARE THEY--
CORRECTION, CAPTAIN.
THE PROVIDERS
ARE NOT OURS.
WE ARE THEIRS.
WHAT DO THEY WANT
FROM US?
YOU ARE TO BE TRAINED,
OF COURSE.
WHAT OTHER USE IS THERE
FOR THRALLS?
THRALLS?
YOU MUST BE MISTAKEN.
WE'RE OFFICERS...
OF A UNITED SPACESHIP...
ON FEDERATION BUSINESS.
THERE HAS BEEN NO MISTAKE.
YOUR OLD TITLES
MEAN NOTHING HERE,
CAPTAIN.
YOU ARE THRALLS NOW.
YOU ARE TO BE TAKEN
TO THE TRAINING
ENCLOSURE.
[BUZZ]
COME.
PLACES HAVE BEEN
PREPARED FOR YOU.
WE'RE NOT
GOING ANYWHERE...
UNTIL WE HAVE
SOME INFORMATION.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING TO
DO WITH US?
I AM GALT,
THE MASTER THRALL.
THIS PLACE IS
THE PLANET TRISKELION.
YOU ARE TO BE TRAINED
AND SPEND THE REST
OF YOUR LIVES HERE.
MR. SPOCK...
I'VE CHECKED
THAT TRANSPORTER
FROM ONE END
TO THE OTHER.
EVERY CIRCUIT
WORKS PERFECTLY.
WHATEVER THAT
POWER SURGE WAS,
IT HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE TRANSPORTER
OR WITH ANY OTHER
SYSTEM ABOARD THIS SHIP.
I'M BEGINNING
TO BELIEVE THAT,
MR. SCOTT.
I'VE CONDUCTED
TWO SWEEPS OF
THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
THERE IS NO
SIGN OF LIFE.
THEN WHAT THE DEVIL
IS HAPPENING?
DOES THAT MEAN
THEIR ATOMS
ARE JUST
FLOATING AROUND
OUT THERE?
NO, DOCTOR.
EVEN THAT
WOULD SHOW UP
ON OUR SENSORS.
WHERE ARE THEY THEN?
THE ONLY ANSWERS
ARE NEGATIVE.
NO MAGNETIC STORMS,
NO IONIC
INTERFERENCE,
NO BREAKDOWN
IN YOUR EQUIPMENT.
A NEGATIVE ATTITUDE
IS NO GOOD TO US.
WE CAN'T JUST
LEAVE THEM
OUT THERE,
WHEREVER THEY ARE.
WE SHALL CONTINUE
SENSOR SCANS, DOCTOR.
AT THE MOMENT,
THAT IS ALL WE CAN DO,
EXCEPT HOPE FOR
A RATIONAL EXPLANATION.
HOPE?
I ALWAYS THOUGHT THAT WAS
A HUMAN FAILING,
MR. SPOCK.
TRUE, DOCTOR.
CONSTANT EXPOSURE
DOES RESULT IN
A CERTAIN DEGREE
OF CONTAMINATION.
THESE ARE YOUR QUARTERS.
OPEN, THRALLS.
AAH!
THAT WAS FOOLISH,
CAPTAIN.
ESCAPE IS
QUITE IMPOSSIBLE...
AS DEMONSTRATED
BY YOUR COLLARS
OF OBEDIENCE.
RETURN TO
YOUR QUARTERS.
THEY ARE NOT
WITHIN THE CONFINES
OF THIS SOLAR SYSTEM.
IT'S BEEN
NEARLY AN HOUR.
CAN PEOPLE
LIVE THAT LONG AS
DISASSEMBLED ATOMS
IN A TRANSPORTER
BEAM?
I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF
THE STUDY BEING DONE,
BUT IT WOULD BE
A FASCINATING PROJECT.
FASCINATING?
THOSE PEOPLE ARE
FRIENDS OF OURS
OUT THERE,
IF THEY'RE STILL ALIVE.
PRECISELY.
THE ODDS ARE NOT GOOD.
NO. I WOULD SAY
APPROXIMATELY 400--
DON'T QUOTE ODDS
AND DON'T GIVE ME
ANY MORE DISPASSIONATE
LOGIC, MR. SPOCK.
JUST KEEP LOOKING
FOR THEM.
I WOULD WELCOME
A SUGGESTION, DOCTOR,
EVEN AN EMOTIONAL ONE,
AS TO WHERE TO LOOK.
FIRST TIME YOU'VE EVER
ASKED ME FOR ANYTHING,
AND IT HAS TO BE
AN OCCASION LIKE THIS.
Chekov: CAPTAIN,
THE ENTERPRISE.
THEY WILL BE TRYING
TO FIND US, WON'T THEY?
THEY'LL TRY, BUT WHERE
DO THEY LOOK?
WE'RE HERE, AND WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE IT IS.
THIS SYSTEM'S STAR
IS A TRINARY.
LIMITS IT A BIT,
BUT WE'RE A LONG WAY
FROM THE "ENTERPRISE,"
IF WE'RE EVEN
IN THE SAME DIMENSION.
I AM YOUR
DRILL THRALL.
I AM CALLED LARS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM HER?
THAT IS NOT
YOUR CONCERN.
YOUR DRILL THRALLS WILL
ATTEND YOU PRESENTLY.
THERE IS LITTLE TIME.
Uhura:
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
AAH! AAH!
GET OUT!
I HAVE BEEN
SELECTED FOR YOU.
LIEUTENANT,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[STRUGGLING]
AAH!
LIEUTENANT!
LIEUTENANT, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
LIEUTENANT,
ANSWER ME!
AAH!
LIEUTENANT!
WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO LIEUTENANT UHURA?!
LIEUTENANT,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
IT IS NOT ALLOWED
TO REFUSE SELECTION.
[BEEP]
STEP AWAY
FROM THE DOOR.
[BEEP]
COME.
IT IS THE NOURISHMENT
INTERVAL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 3259.2.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
IN COMMAND.
THE CAPTAIN,
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
AND ENSIGN CHEKOV
HAVE BEEN MISSING
FOR NEARLY TWO HOURS.
COMPUTER
PROBABILITY PROJECTIONS
ARE USELESS
DUE TO INSUFFICIENT DATA.
MR. SPOCK, I'M GETTING
A FLUCTUATING ENERGY READING
ON THIS HYDROGEN CLOUD.
IT'S FAINT, SIR,
BUT IT CONSISTENTLY
READS IN EXCESS
OF PREDICTABLE
ENERGY LEVEL.
INTERESTING.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
AN IONIZATION TRAIL.
WHAT WOULD ACCOUNT
FOR THAT, SPOCK?
EXACTLY THE QUESTION
I HAVE JUST FED TO
THE COMPUTERS, DOCTOR.
AND THE ANSWER IS...
NOTHING KNOWN TO US
WOULD ACCOUNT FOR IT.
WELL, THE TRANSPORTER
HAS NEITHER THE POWER
NOR THE RANGE
TO ACCOUNT FOR THAT.
PLOT A FOLLOW COURSE,
ENSIGN HAINES.
AYE, SIR.
YOU'RE GOING
TO LEAVE HERE
WITHOUT THEM
AND RUN OFF ON SOME
WILD GOOSE CHASE
HALFWAY ACROSS
THE GALAXY
JUST BECAUSE
YOU FOUND A DISCREPANCY
IN A HYDROGEN CLOUD?
DOCTOR,
I AM CHASING THE CAPTAIN,
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
AND ENSIGN CHEKOV,
NOT SOME WILD
AQUATIC FOWL.
THIS IS THE ONLY LEAD
WE'VE HAD.
COURSE PLOTTED
AND LAID IN,
MR. SPOCK.
310 MARK 241.
INITIATE.
WARP FACTOR 2.
YOU, YOU HAVE BEEN
SELECTED FOR ME?
[DEEP VOICE] NO. I AM
ONLY YOUR DRILL THRALL.
I HAVE
BROUGHT YOU NOURISHMENT.
IT IS A NICE NAME,
CHEE-KOO.
HEH HEH.
CHEKOV.
CHEE-KOOF!
IT IS A VERY NICE NAME.
I AM CALLED TAMOON.
OH, PLEASED, PLEASED
TO KNOW YOU, MISS.
YOU ARE A FINE SPECIMEN.
I LIKE YOU BETTER
THAN THE OTHERS.
I WILL
INSTRUCT YOU WELL,
SO MY PROVIDER
WILL TAKE YOU.
THAT'S V-V-VERY KIND
OF YOU, MISS, BUT--
IF MY PROVIDER
IS PLEASED,
WE MAY EVEN BE SELECTED
FOR EACH OTHER.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
I WAS SO HUNGRY.
WHATEVER YOU CALL THIS,
IT WAS VERY GOOD.
IT IS NOURISHMENT.
WE CALL IT THAT.
NOURISHMENT.
THAT'S VERY PRACTICAL.
WHAT DO YOU CALL
THIS COLLAR?
IT IS A SIGN
OF OUR PROVIDER.
BY THE COLOR OF THE LIGHTS,
IT CAN BE KNOWN WHO HOLDS US.
WHEN YOU ARE VENDED,
YOU WILL ALSO
HAVE A COLOR.
VENDED? YOU MEAN
BOUGHT, SOLD.
WHEN YOU ARE
DEVELOPED.
THE PROVIDER
WHO OFFERS
THE MOST QUATLOOS
PUTS HIS COLOR ON US.
OUR RACE HAS
ANOTHER NAME FOR IT.
SLAVERY.
THIS...
COLLAR OF OBEDIENCE...
IS GALT THE ONLY ONE
WHO CAN OPERATE IT?
IT IS ONLY
TO WARN AND PUNISH.
HOW DOES HE WORK IT?
IT IS NOT PERMITTED
TO TALK OF THAT.
WILL YOU PROVIDE
ALL MY NOURISHMENT?
OF COURSE.
I AM YOUR DRILL THRALL.
I WILL TRAIN YOU WELL.
YES, I'M SURE YOU WILL.
I MUST SAY,
I'VE NEVER SEEN
A TOP SERGEANT
WHO LOOKED LIKE YOU.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
IT MEANS YOU'RE
A VERY BEAUTIFUL WOMAN.
WHAT IS...BEAUTIFUL?
YOU MEAN NOBODY'S EVER
TOLD YOU THAT BEFORE?
WELL, UH,
BEAUTIFUL IS, UM...
BEAUTIFUL...
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
SHAHNA,
WHERE WERE YOU BORN?
BORN?
I HAVE BEEN HERE
ALWAYS.
YOUR PARENTS--
WHERE ARE THEY?
YOUR MOTHER
AND FATHER.
SHE WHO BORE ME WAS KILLED
IN A FREESTYLE MATCH.
FREESTYLE?
YOU WILL LEARN
ALL THESE THINGS.
LARS AND CHEKOV'S
DRILL THRALL.
THEY WEREN'T BORN HERE.
WHERE DO THEY COME FROM?
IT IS NOT PERMITTED--
THE EXERCISE INTERVAL.
THIS IS YOUR
TRAINING HARNESS.
PUT IT ON.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
NOTHING OUT THERE.
NOTHING OUT THERE
AT ALL.
WE CERTAINLY SEEM
TO BE HEADING INTO
AN EMPTY SECTOR.
PROJECTING BACK
ALONG THE PATH
OF IONIZATION,
THE NEAREST SYSTEM
IS M24 ALPHA.
THAT MUST BE
TWO DOZEN LIGHT YEARS AWAY.
11.630.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT THEY COULD HAVE
TRANSPORTED
OVER A DISTANCE OF...
YOU'RE OUT OF YOUR
VULCAN MIND, SPOCK.
I'M SUGGESTING NOTHING,
DOCTOR.
I'M MERELY PURSUING
THE ONLY LOGICAL COURSE
AVAILABLE TO US.
HOLD.
THIS THRALL WAS SLOW
IN OBEYING A COMMAND.
FOR HIS PUNISHMENT,
HE WILL BE PRACTICE TARGET.
AS YOU CHARGE,
YOU WILL STRIKE
THE PRACTICE TARGET
WHEN YOU PASS.
YOU BEGIN, UHURA.
NO!
IT IS NOT ALLOWED TO REFUSE
A TRAINING EXERCISE.
I DON'T CARE WHETHER
IT'S ALLOWED OR NOT.
I WILL NOT DO IT.
NONE OF US
WILL DO IT, GALT.
IT IS PART OF YOUR TRAINING.
THE PROVIDERS WISH IT.
THE DEVIL WITH
THE PROVIDERS.
COSSACKS.
[CHOKING]
WE HAVE BEEN TOLERANT
BECAUSE YOU ARE NEWCOMERS,
BUT I SEE YOU MUST
BE GIVEN A LESSON.
LARS.
KLOOG.
KLOOG WILL ADMINISTER
CORRECTION.
UHURA, TAKE YOUR PLACE
ON THE TRIAD.
TIE HER.
NO.
NO!
I AM RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE ACTIONS
OF MY PEOPLE.
I DEMAND TO SEE
THE PROVIDERS.
IT IS NOT PERMITTED.
BUT, CAPTAIN,
SINCE YOU ASSUME
RESPONSIBILITY
FOR YOUR PEOPLE,
YOU WILL TAKE
THE PUNISHMENT.
IT IS LESS PAINFUL
THAN THE COLLAR.
TURN AROUND.
CAPTAIN, YOU WILL BE
PRACTICE TARGET.
IT IS A SHAME
TO LOSE YOU, CAPTAIN,
BUT IT IS WORTH IT
AS AN EXAMPLE
TO THE OTHERS.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL.
STARDATE, UNKNOWN.
OUR STRANGE CAPTIVITY
CONTINUES.
THIS PLANET IS CALLED
TRISKELION.
WE DO NOT KNOW
ITS LOCATION.
WHO CONTROLS IT.
ITS DANGERS...
ARE ABUNDANTLY CLEAR.
HOLD.
REST INTERVAL.
15 TRISECS.
HE'S PRETTY FAST
WITH THAT WHIP.
THIS WILL
STRENGTHEN YOU.
DRINK IT.
KLOOG'S LEFT EYE
IS WEAK.
APPROACH HIM
FROM THAT SIDE.
RESUME PLACES.
Voice: HOLD.
WE HOLD, PROVIDER 1.
PROVIDER 1 BIDS
300 QUATLOOS
FOR THE NEWCOMERS.
PROVIDER 2,
350 QUATLOOS.
PROVIDER 3, 400.
1,000 QUATLOOS.
1,050 QUATLOOS.
2,000.
2,000 QUATLOOS ARE BID.
IS THERE A CHALLENGE?
THE NEWCOMERS
HAVE BEEN VENDED
TO PROVIDER 1.
WE'RE FREE PEOPLE.
WE BELONG TO NO ONE.
SUCH SPIRIT.
I WAGER 15 QUATLOOS
THAT HE IS UNTRAINABLE.
20 QUATLOOS THAT
ALL 3 ARE UNTRAINABLE.
5,000 QUATLOOS
THAT THE NEWCOMERS
WILL HAVE
TO BE DESTROYED.
ACCEPTED.
MARK THEM, GALT.
YOU NOW BEAR THE MARK
OF A FINE HERD.
BUT I MUST WARN YOU--
ANY FURTHER DISOBEDIENCE
NOW THAT YOU ARE
FULL-FLEDGED THRALLS
WILL BE PUNISHABLE
BY DEATH.
MR. SPOCK, IT JUST
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE
THEY COULD HAVE COME
THIS FAR.
IF THERE'S
ANY CHANCE AT ALL, IT'S
TO CONTINUE TO SEARCH
IN THE AREA THEY WERE LOST.
WE SEARCHED THE AREA.
IT'S ALWAYS POSSIBLE
TO MISS SOMETHING.
SUCH AS A FAILURE IN
THE TRANSPORTER MECHANISM.
NO, SIR.
THERE WAS NO SIGN
OF FAILURE.
THERE WAS NO SIGN OF THEM
IN THE AREA OF GAMMA 2.
IF THEY WEREN'T
THERE, IT'S
JUST RIDICULOUS
TO THINK THEY COULD
STILL BE ALIVE,
NOT AFTER
ALL THIS TIME.
IN THAT CASE, DOCTOR,
WE HAVE NOTHING TO LOSE
BY PURSUING
OUR PRESENT COURSE.
SLOW DOWN.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WE'VE COVERED
OVER 2 MILES.
CAN WE TAKE A BREATHER?
A REST?
OH. VERY WELL.
IF YOU ARE TIRED.
OH.
WELL, IT'S GOOD
TO GET AWAY
FROM THAT
DEVELOPMENT AREA,
EVEN FOR A WHILE.
SHAHNA, WHY DO THE,
UH, PROVIDERS...
WHY DO THEY LIKE
TO WATCH OTHERS
BEING HURT...
KILLED?
THAT IS THE WAY.
THEIR VOICES SOUND...
MECHANICAL.
ARE THEY COMPUTERS?
COMPUTERS?
YOU'VE SEEN THEM.
DO THEY HAVE BODIES?
NOT SUCH AS OURS.
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
IT IS NOT USED.
IT'S VERY OLD.
DOES IT HAVE A NAME?
SHAHNA.
COULD IT
HAVE BEEN A CITY
FOR THE PROVIDERS?
I DO NOT THINK
IT IS WELL
TO ASK SUCH THINGS.
BUT THEY DO HAVE BODIES,
OR DID HAVE?
ONE DOES NOT TALK
OF SUCH THINGS.
UH...
IT'S VERY PRETTY COUNTRY.
VERY MUCH LIKE
MY HOME PLANET EARTH.
PLANET?
WHERE I WAS BORN.
SHAHNA...
DON'T YOU EVER LOOK
AT THE NIGHT SKY?
THE LIGHTS UP THERE?
I HAVE LOOKED AT THEM.
WELL, THOSE ARE STARS.
AND AROUND THEM...
ARE PLANETS.
AND THERE ARE PEOPLE
THAT LIVE ON THEM,
JUST LIKE US.
HOW CAN ONE LIVE
ON A FLICKER OF LIGHT?
FROM EARTH,
TRISKELION'S 3 SUNS
ARE JUST A FLICKER
OF LIGHT.
ACTUALLY, THIS IS
THE DARKEST PLANET
I'VE EVER SEEN.
DARK?
BUT ALL IS LIGHTED.
HERE, THE CHAMBERS.
THE THRALLS
HAVE NO FREEDOM, SHAHNA.
YOU DON'T THINK
OR DO ANYTHING
BUT WHAT THE PROVIDERS
TELL YOU.
WHAT ELSE WOULD ONE DO?
LOVE...
FOR ONE THING.
WHAT IS...LOVE?
LOVE...
IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
ON EARTH...
ESPECIALLY TO A MAN
AND A WOMAN.
WE, TOO, HAVE MATES.
WHEN IT IS TIME
TO INCREASE THE HERD,
MY PROVIDER WILL
SELECT ONE FOR ME.
ON EARTH...
WE SELECT OUR OWN MATE.
SOMEONE WE CARE FOR.
ON EARTH...
MEN AND WOMEN LIVE TOGETHER,
HELP EACH OTHER...
MAKE EACH OTHER HAPPY.
I DO NOT THINK
YOUR WORDS ARE ALLOWED.
ALL RIGHT.
TELL ME ABOUT
THE PROVIDERS.
WHAT DO THEY
LOOK LIKE?
WHERE
DO THEY LIVE?
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THEM,
BUT...THEY ARE SAID
NOT TO BE LIKE US.
THEY STAY IN--
[ELECTRONIC BUZZING]
OH!
STOP IT.
STOP IT!
I'M RESPONSIBLE!
I MADE HER TALK!
STOP IT!
YOU'RE KILLING HER!
SHE DID NOTHING WRONG!
IT WAS MY FAULT.
IF YOU WANT
TO PUNISH SOMEONE,
PUNISH ME!
PLEASE.
[SHAHNA GASPING]
Provider: IS THAT WHAT
YOU HUMANS CALL COMPASSION?
IT IS INTERESTING,
BUT IT HAS NO VALUE HERE.
YOU PRESENT MANY INTERESTING
ASPECTS, CAPTAIN,
BUT YOU MUST LEARN
OBEDIENCE.
THEN YOU WILL BE
AN EXCELLENT THRALL.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN STOP CRYING NOW,
SHAHNA.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU--YOU RISKED
BRINGING THEIR ANGER
ON YOURSELF.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
IT'S THE CUSTOM
OF MY PEOPLE...
TO HELP ONE ANOTHER
WHEN WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
AND...
AND THIS...
IS THIS...
ALSO HELPING?
YOU COULD CALL IT THAT.
PLEASE...
HELP ME ONCE AGAIN.
I...
I DID NOT KNOW
IT COULD BE LIKE THIS
BETWEEN PEOPLE.
IS IT ALWAYS SO IN
THE PLACE YOU COME FROM?
CAPTAIN,
YOU DO INDEED
PRESENT MANY
SURPRISES.
BECAUSE
YOU HAVE AMUSED
THE PROVIDERS,
THERE WILL BE
NO PUNISHMENT.
RETURN TO
YOUR QUARTERS.
MR. SCOTT,
CAN WE MANAGE
ANYTHING FASTER
THAN WARP 6?
IT'S MY OPINION
THAT WE'VE GONE TOO FAR
AS IT IS, SIR.
HE'S RIGHT, SPOCK.
WE'VE LOST JIM
AND THE OTHERS
BACK ON GAMMA 2.
NOW YOU'VE
DRAGGED US OUT HERE
A DOZEN LIGHT YEARS
ON SOME WILD HUNCH--
DOCTOR, I DO NOT RESPOND
TO HUNCHES.
NO TRANSPORTER MALFUNCTION
WAS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE DISAPPEARANCE.
THEY WERE NOT WITHIN
THE GAMMA SYSTEM.
A FOCUSED BEAM
OF EXTREMELY
HIGH-INTENSITY LIGHT
WAS DIRECTED INTO
THE GAMMA SYSTEM
FROM THE TRINARY SYSTEM
WE ARE NOW APPROACHING.
NO KNOWN
NATURAL PHENOMENA
COULD HAVE CAUSED
THAT BEAM.
DOES THAT CLARIFY
THE SITUATION?
NO, IT DOESN'T,
MR. SPOCK.
IT'S STILL
A FANCY WAY
OF SAYING
THAT YOU'RE PLAYING
A HUNCH.
WELL, MY HUNCH IS
THAT THEY'RE BACK
ON GAMMA 2,
DEAD OR ALIVE,
AND I STILL WANT
ANOTHER SEARCH.
DR. McCOY SPEAKS
FOR ME, TOO, SIR.
I SEE.
GENTLEMEN,
I AM IN COMMAND
OF THIS VESSEL,
AND WE SHALL CONTINUE
ON OUR PRESENT COURSE,
UNLESS IT IS
YOUR INTENTION
TO DECLARE A MUTINY.
MR. SPOCK.
WHO SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT A MUTINY,
YOU STUBBORN,
POINTED-EARED...
ALL RIGHT.
IF WE DON'T
FIND THEM HERE,
DO WE STILL HAVE
ANOTHER SEARCH
ON GAMMA 2?
AGREED.
MR. SCOTT,
COULD YOU MANAGE WARP 7?
I WOULD BE MORE THAN
CONTENT TO DO SO, SIR,
AND MAYBE A WEE BIT MORE.
ENSIGN...
WARP 7.
YOU'RE DISTURBED ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TODAY?
YES.
YOU HAVE MADE ME FEEL...
STRANGELY.
IF IT WERE ALLOWED,
I WOULD ASK THAT
YOU HAVE ANOTHER
DRILL THRALL.
I WOULDN'T LIKE THAT,
SHAHNA.
I WOULDN'T LIKE THAT
AT ALL.
I'M SORRY, SHAHNA.
[BEEPS]
THIS IS GOING TO KILL
OUR ROMANCE.
WHAT ABOUT LARS?
HE'S GONE
TO REPORT ME.
I TOLD HIM
I DIDN'T LIKE THE FOOD.
I THINK GALT
IS THE ONLY ONE
WHO CONTROLS
THESE COLLARS.
IF WE CAN FIND
THE PHASER
THAT I THREW
AT LARS,
WE CAN USE
THE CIRCUITS
TO SHORT OUT
THESE COLLARS.
CAPTAIN.
Provider:
ONLY A REMINDER.
YOU EARTH PEOPLE
ARE MOST UNUSUAL,
MOST STIMULATING.
STANDARD ORBIT.
SENSORS INDICATE
ONLY ONE CONCENTRATION
OF LIFE FORMS
ON THE PLANET--
ON THE LOWER HEMISPHERE.
HUMANOID READINGS.
WELL, AT LEAST
THAT GIVES
OUR LANDING FORCE
A STARTING POINT.
THERE WILL BE
NO LANDING FORCE, DOCTOR.
ASSUMING THE CAPTAIN
AND THE OTHERS
ARE STILL ALIVE,
IT WOULD BE UNWISE
TO ENDANGER THEM
BY BEAMING DOWN
A LARGE CONTINGENT.
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO LEAVE THEM THERE
WHILE WE JUST SIT
AND WAIT.
INTERESTING.
NO POWER SOURCE.
IT MAY BE SHIELDED.
AND IT MAY BE JUST
A WILD GOOSE CHASE
LIKE WE'VE BEEN
TELLING YOU.
I SHALL BEAM DOWN,
DOCTOR.
IF I'M UNABLE
TO COMMUNICATE,
A LANDING PARTY
MAY BE NECESSARY.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
IF YOU'RE GOING
INTO THE LION'S DEN,
YOU'LL NEED
A MEDICAL OFFICER.
DANIEL, AS I RECALL,
HAD ONLY HIS FAITH.
BUT I WELCOME
YOUR COMPANY, DOCTOR.
MR. SCOTT,
YOU'LL BE IN COMMAND.
AYE, SIR.
Provider:
NO, MR. SPOCK,
YOU WILL NOT
LEAVE THE SHIP.
NONE OF YOUR
CONTROL SYSTEMS
WILL OPERATE.
McCoy: WHAT THE DEVIL'S
GOING ON?
SPOCK?
SPOCK!
Kirk: SPOCK!
WELCOME TO TRISKELION,
GENTLEMEN.
BY NOW
IT MUST BE OBVIOUS TO YOU
THAT YOU HAVE BEEN EXPECTED.
WHAT THE VOICE SAID
WAS TRUE, SIR.
NOTHING
IS FUNCTIONING.
Provider:
COMMENDATIONS, GENTLEMEN.
YOUR INGENUITY
IN DISCOVERING
THE WHEREABOUTS
OF YOUR COMPANIONS
IS NOTEWORTHY.
Kirk: WHAT YOU'RE
HEARING, GENTLEMEN,
IS A PROVIDER.
WE ARE KNOWN
TO THE THRALLS
AS PROVIDERS
BECAUSE WE PROVIDE
FOR ALL THEIR NEEDS.
THE TERM IS EASIER
FOR THEIR LIMITED
MENTAL ABILITIES
TO COMPREHEND.
"PROVIDING FOR
ALL THEIR NEEDS"
MEANS USING THRALLS--
PEOPLE STOLEN
FROM OTHER PARTS
OF THE GALAXY
TO FIGHT EACH OTHER,
AND THE PROVIDERS
GAMBLE ON THE WINNER.
FASCINATING.
BUT THESE...PROVIDERS
HAVEN'T THE COURAGE
TO SHOW THEMSELVES.
Provider: YOUR SPECIES HAS
GREAT CURIOSITY.
WE KNEW THAT.
YOU ARE INTERESTING
IN MANY WAYS.
BUT YOU ARE AFRAID?
Provider: YOU PRESENT NO DANGER
WHILE YOU WEAR THE COLLAR,
AND YOU WEAR IT
AS LONG AS YOU LIVE.
THEN SHOW YOURSELF.
Provider: THERE IS NO OBJECTION.
THE POWER SOURCE...
SHIELDED BY SOLID ROCK.
Provider 1:
WE ARE 1,000 OF YOUR METERS
BENEATH THE SURFACE.
PRIMARY...
MENTAL EVOLUTION.
INCREDIBLE.
Provider 2:
THAT IS NOT TRUE, CAPTAIN.
ONCE WE HAD
HUMANOID FORM,
BUT WE EVOLVED
BEYOND IT.
Provider 3: THROUGH EONS
OF DEVOTING OURSELVES
EXCLUSIVELY TO
INTELLECTUAL PURSUITS,
WE BECAME
THE PHYSICALLY SIMPLE,
MENTALLY SUPERIOR
CREATURE
YOU SEE BEFORE YOU.
A SPECIES THAT ENSLAVES
OTHER BEINGS
IS...
HARDLY SUPERIOR,
MENTALLY OR OTHERWISE.
THE THRALLS ARE NECESSARY
TO THE GAMES.
WE HAVE FOUND
ATHLETIC COMPETITIONS
OUR ONLY CHALLENGE--
THE ONLY THING
WHICH FURNISHES US
WITH PURPOSE.
IT'S AN UNPRODUCTIVE
PURPOSE,
UNWORTHY
OF YOUR INTELLECT.
WE USE
ONLY INFERIOR BEINGS.
WE HAVE FOUND...
THAT ALL LIFE FORMS
IN THE GALAXY
ARE CAPABLE
OF SUPERIOR DEVELOPMENT.
PERHAPS YOU'RE
NOT AS EVOLVED
AS YOU BELIEVE.
AN INTERESTING
SPECULATION, CAPTAIN.
YOU AND YOUR PEOPLE
ARE MOST CHALLENGING.
YES, MOST CHALLENGING.
IT WAS HOPED
THAT SUCH NEW BLOOD
WOULD STIMULATE
OUR STOCK OF THRALLS.
HOW UNFORTUNATE THAT
YOU MUST BE DESTROYED.
OUR DESTRUCTION WILL RESULT
ONLY IN YOUR OWN.
YOU MAY CONTROL
THE "ENTERPRISE,"
BUT YOU CANNOT
MATCH THE FORCE
OF THE ENTIRE FEDERATION.
YOUR SHIP WILL
BE DESTROYED
BY A MAGNETIC STORM.
NO COMMUNICATIONS
WITH YOUR BASE
WILL BE POSSIBLE.
YOUR FATE WILL REMAIN
A MYSTERY TO YOUR PEOPLE.
AND YOU CALL YOURSELVES
SUPERIOR!
YOU'RE MURDERERS
WITHOUT THE SPIRIT
TO REALLY WAGER
FOR THE LIVES YOU TAKE.
WAGER? EXPLAIN YOURSELF,
CAPTAIN.
MY PEOPLE PRIDE
THEMSELVES
ON BEING THE GREATEST,
MOST SUCCESSFUL
GAMBLERS
IN THE UNIVERSE.
WE COMPETE FOR EVERYTHING--
POWER, FAME, WOMEN--
EVERYTHING WE DESIRE,
AND IT IS OUR NATURE...
TO WIN.
AND FOR PROOF,
I OFFER YOU
OUR EXPLORATION
OF THIS GALAXY.
WE ARE AWARE
OF YOUR COMPETITIVE
ABILITIES, CAPTAIN.
WELL, THEN...
I WAGER...
THAT WITH WEAPONS
OF YOUR OWN CHOICE,
RIGHT HERE AND NOW,
MY PEOPLE CAN OVERCOME
AN EQUAL NUMBER OF THRALLS
SET AGAINST US.
100 QUATLOOS
ON THE NEWCOMERS.
400 QUATLOOS AGAINST
THE NEWCOMERS.
200 QUATLOOS AGAINST!
500 FOR THE NEWCOMERS.
CONTEST BY MULTIPLE
ELIMINATION.
WAIT! WAIT!
HEAR ME!
WE CAN'T WAGER FOR TRIFLES
LIKE QUATLOOS.
THE STAKES MUST BE HIGHER.
NAME YOUR STAKES,
CAPTAIN.
IF WE WIN,
THE "ENTERPRISE"
AND ITS CREW
LEAVES HERE IN SAFETY.
FURTHERMORE, ALL THE THRALLS
ON THE PLANET MUST BE FREED.
ANARCHY.
THEY WOULD STARVE.
YOU WILL EDUCATE
AND TRAIN THEM
TO ESTABLISH A NORMAL
SELF-GOVERNING CULTURE.
THRALLS GOVERN THEMSELVES?
RIDICULOUS!
WE HAVE DONE THE SAME
WITH CULTURES
THROUGHOUT THE GALAXY.
ARE YOU WILLING
TO ADMIT
THAT WE CAN DO SOMETHING
YOU CAN'T?
THERE IS NOTHING
WE CANNOT DO!
AND IF YOU LOSE,
CAPTAIN?
IF WE LOSE...
WE WILL REMAIN HERE,
THE ENTIRE CREW
OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
THE MOST STUBBORN,
DETERMINED COMPETITORS
IN THE UNIVERSE.
WE'LL BECOME THRALLS,
ENTER YOUR GAMES,
OBEY YOUR ORDERS
WITHOUT REBELLION.
YOU'LL BE ASSURED
OF GENERATIONS
OF THE MOST EXCITING
WAGERING YOU'VE EVER HAD.
YOUR STAKES ARE INDEED
HIGH, CAPTAIN.
NOT FOR TRUE GAMESTERS.
WE WILL ACCEPT
YOUR STAKES
ON ONE CONDITION.
NAME IT.
AS LEADER
OF YOUR PEOPLE,
YOUR SPIRIT SEEMS
MOST INDOMITABLE.
WE SUGGEST YOU ALONE,
PITTED AGAINST
3 CONTESTANTS
OF OUR CHOOSING.
3 AGAINST ONE...
THOSE ARE
PRETTY HIGH ODDS.
NOT FOR TRUE
GAMESTERS, CAPTAIN.
YOUR...YOUR TERMS
ARE UNFAIR.
ON THE CONTRARY,
THEY'RE EXTREMELY
FAIR,
SINCE YOUR
ALTERNATIVE
IS DEATH.
WELL, IN THAT CASE,
I'LL ACCEPT YOUR TERMS.
GALT WILL
PREPARE YOU.
Provider: BECAUSE YOU WAGER
YOUR SKILL FOR ALL YOUR PEOPLE,
THEY WILL BE PERMITTED
TO WATCH THE OUTCOME
OF THE GAME
ON THE SHIP'S
VIEW SCREEN.
MR. SPOCK, LOOK!
Provider: CAPTAIN,
YOU WILL DEFEND.
THRALLS MUST STAY
IN THE BLUE AREA.
YOU WILL
TAKE THE YELLOW.
TOUCHING
AN OPPOSING COLOR
DEPRIVES A CONTESTANT
OF ONE WEAPON.
AN OPPONENT
MUST BE KILLED
TO BE REMOVED
FROM THE GAME.
IF ONLY WOUNDED,
HE IS REPLACED
BY A FRESH THRALL.
IS THAT CLEAR, CAPTAIN?
YES, THAT'S CLEAR.
WHAT IN THE NAME
OF HEAVEN IS THIS?
HEAVEN'S GOT VERY LITTLE
TO DO WITH THIS.
SHAHNA.
YOU LIED.
EVERYTHING YOU SAID.
THE THRALLS...
SURRENDER!
Provider: YOU HAVE WON,
CAPTAIN KIRK,
UNFORTUNATELY.
HOWEVER, THE TERMS OF THE WAGER
WILL BE HONORED.
YOU ARE FREE.
REMOVE YOUR COLLARS.
THE THRALLS
WILL BE TRAINED?
THEY WILL BE TRAINED.
WE HAVE SAID IT.
I THINK
YOU'LL FIND IT
A MUCH MORE
EXCITING GAME
THAN THE ONE
YOU'VE BEEN PLAYING.
I'M SORRY, SHAHNA.
I DIDN'T LIE.
I DID
WHAT WAS NECESSARY.
SOMEDAY, I HOPE
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND...
A LITTLE.
YOU WILL LEAVE US NOW?
YES.
TO GO BACK TO THE LIGHTS
IN THE SKY?
YES.
I WOULD LIKE TO GO
TO THOSE LIGHTS WITH YOU.
TAKE ME?
I CAN'T.
THEN TEACH ME HOW,
AND I WILL FOLLOW YOU.
THERE'S SO MUCH YOU MUST
LEARN HERE FIRST.
THE PROVIDERS
WILL TEACH YOU.
LEARN IT, SHAHNA.
ALL YOUR PEOPLE
MUST LEARN
BEFORE YOU CAN REACH
FOR THE STARS.
SHAHNA...
SCOTTY!
Scotty:
AYE, SIR.
BEAM US UP.
GOOD-BYE, JIM KIRK.
I WILL LEARN...
AND WATCH THE LIGHTS
IN THE SKY...
AND REMEMBER.