APPROACHING
SIGMA IOTA 2,
CAPTAIN.
STANDARD ORBIT,
MR. CHEKOV.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE
RECEIVED VOCAL CONTACT
FROM
AN OFFICIAL STATION.
THEY RELAYED US
TO A MAN NAME OKMYX.
HIS TITLE IS "BOSS."
HA, HA.
BOSS?
ALL RIGHT, LIEUTENANT,
PUT HIM ON.
OKMYX.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE,
REPRESENTING
THE FEDERATION
OF PLANETS.
HELLO, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE FROM THE SAME
OUTFIT AS THE HORIZON?
YES. UNFORTUNATELY,
THE HORIZON WAS LOST
WITH ALL HANDS
SHORTLY AFTER
LEAVING YOUR PLANET.
WE ONLY RECEIVED
HER RADIO REPORT
LAST MONTH.
LAST MONTH?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THE HORIZON LEFT HERE
100 YEARS AGO.
A LITTLE DIFFICULT
TO EXPLAIN.
WE RECEIVED A REPORT
100 YEARS LATE
BECAUSE IT WAS SENT
BY CONVENTIONAL RADIO.
YOUR SYSTEM IS
ON THE OUTER REACHES
OF THE GALAXY.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE
SUBSPACE COMMUNICATION
IN THOSE DAYS.
TOWARD
THE EDGE OF WHAT?
I'LL EXPLAIN IT IN MORE
DETAIL WHEN I SEE YOU.
THE SHIP WON'T LAND,
BUT WE'LL TRANSPORT
SEVERAL PEOPLE DOWN.
WELL, THAT'S
A LITTLE DIFFICULT
FOR YOU
TO UNDERSTAND, TOO.
I'LL EXPLAIN IT
IN MORE DETAIL
WHEN I SEE YOU.
WHERE WILL
BE CONVENIENT?
WELL, THERE'S AN INTERSECTION
JUST AT THE END
OF THE BLOCK
NEAR A YELLOW
FIRE PLUG.
THINK YOU CAN YOU FIND IT?
YELLOW FIRE PLUG--
SCOTTY, DO YOU
HAVE THE COORDINATES?
LOCATED, SIR.
GOOD.
MR. OKMYX,
WE HAVE YOUR
INTERSECTION LOCATED.
WILL FIVE MINUTES
BE ALL RIGHT?
FINE. FINE.
I'LL HAVE A RECEPTION
COMMITTEE THERE
TO MEET YOU.
GOOD, I'LL BE LOOKING
FORWARD TO IT.
KIRK OUT.
SCOTTY, YOU
HAVE THE COM.
AYE, SIR.
SPOCK, McCOY,
WE'RE BEAMING DOWN.
STANDARD EQUIPMENT.
THE HORIZON'S
CONTACT CAME
BEFORE THE NON-INTERFERENCE
DIRECTIVE WENT INTO EFFECT.
THEY MUST
HAVE INTERFERED
WITH THE NORMAL
EVOLUTION OF
THE PLANET.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING
TO SEE THE RESULTS
OF THE CONTAMINATION.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW THERE
IS A CONTAMINATION.
THE EVIDENCE IS ONLY
CIRCUMSTANTIAL.
WELL, WHAT WAS THE
STATE OF THE IOTIAN
CULTURE
BEFORE
THE HORIZON CAME?
THE BEGINNINGS
OF INDUSTRIALIZATION.
HORIZON REPORTS
INDICATE THE IOTIANS
ARE EXTREMELY INTELLIGENT
AND SOMEWHAT IMITATIVE.
SO WE'RE GOING DOWN
TO RE-CONTAMINATE
THEM.
THE DAMAGE
HAS BEEN DONE, DOCTOR.
WE ARE HERE
TO REPAIR IT.
LET'S NOT
ARGUE ABOUT IT.
LET'S GO STUDY IT.
ENERGIZE.
[CAR HORN BEEPS]
FASCINATING.
THIS IS LIKE COMING HOME.
HOME WAS NEVER
LIKE THIS.
I'VE SEEN PICTURES
OF THE OLD DAYS
THAT LOOK LIKE THIS.
INTERESTING,
CAPTAIN.
PASSERSBY
ARE CARRYING,
I BELIEVE,
FIREARMS.
O.K., YOU THREE,
LET'S SEE YOU PETRIFIED.
SIR, WOULD YOU
MIND EXPLAINING
THAT STATEMENT, PLEASE?
I WANT TO SEE YOU
TURN TO STONE.
PUT YOUR HANDS
OVER YOUR HEAD,
OR YOU AIN'T GOING
TO HAVE NO HEAD
TO PUT YOUR HANDS OVER.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
WHAT'S THIS?
THAT'S A WEAPON.
BE CAREFUL WITH THAT.
A HEATER, HUH?
HEY, THE BOSS
WILL LOVE THAT.
NOW, LOOK, WE WERE
ASKED TO COME DOWN HERE
BY A MR. OKMYX. HE SAID--
I KNOW WHAT HE SAID, BUD.
HE SAID SOME OF
THE BOYS WOULD MEET YOU.
O.K., WE'RE
MEETING YOU.
WELL, THOSE FIREARMS
ARE NOT NECESSARY.
YOU TRYING
TO MAKE TROUBLE?
WHO? ME?
DON'T GIVE ME THOSE
BABY BLUE EYES.
WHAT?
I DON'T GO FOR
THAT INNOCENT ROUTINE.
SIR, DOES EVERYONE HERE
CARRY FIREARMS?
I NEVER HEARD SUCH
STUPID QUESTIONS
IN MY LIFE.
WELL, SINCE THIS
OKMYX ASKED US DOWN
HERE, DON'T YOU
THINK WE SHOULD
SEE HIM?
ALL RIGHT. GET MOVING,
DOWN THE STREET.
AAH!
KRAKO'S GETTING
MORE GALL ALL THE TIME.
IS THIS
HOW YOU GREET
ALL YOUR GUESTS?
IT HAPPENS, PAL.
THAT MAN'S DEAD
BACK THERE.
YEAH, WELL, WE AIN'T
PLAYING FOR PEANUTS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
YOU GUYS NEVER SAW
A HIT BEFORE?
SIR, THERE ARE
SEVERAL QUESTIONS
I WOULD LIKE TO ASK.
ASK THE BOSS.
I DON'T KNOW NOTHING.
GET MOVING.
[McCOY]
THIS IS
THE CONTAMINATION
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
JIM.
YES, BUT THE HORIZON CREW
WASN'T COMPOSED
OF COLD-BLOODED KILLERS.
AND THEY DIDN'T
REPORT THIS CULTURE
IN THIS STATE, EITHER.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HEY, WHEN'S THE BOSS
GOING TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THE CRUMMY
STREETLIGHTS
AROUND HERE, EH?
A GIRL AIN'T SAFE.
YEAH, AND HOW ABOUT
THE LAUNDRY PICKUP?
WE AIN'T HAD A TRUCK
BY IN THREE WEEKS.
WRITE HIM
A LETTER.
I DID.
HE SENT IT BACK
WITH POSTAGE DUE.
LISTEN, WE PAY
OUR PERCENTAGES.
WE'RE ENTITLED TO A LITTLE
SERVICE FOR OUR MONEY, HUH?
GET LOST, WILL YA?
SOME PEOPLE GOT NOTHING
TO DO BUT COMPLAIN.
IS THIS THE WAY YOUR
CITIZENS DO BUSINESS,
THEIR RIGHT OF PETITION?
THEY PAY
THEIR PERCENTAGES
AND THE BOSS
TAKES CARE OF THEM.
[BUZZER]
HIT THAT BUTTON.
YEAH?
GOT THEM, BOSS.
NO SWEAT.
ALL RIGHT, BRING THEM IN.
WHICH ONE OF YOU
GUYS IS THE CAPTAIN?
DEPENDS.
HEH. HA HA HA.
MAKE YOURSELF A
DRINK, CAPTAIN.
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
I DISTILL IT MYSELF.
NO, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE
MR. OKMYX?
THAT'S ME, PAL.
THIS IS MY
FIRST OFFICER,
MR. SPOCK,
DR. McCOY.
DOCTOR, HUH?
PUT THAT
CHOPPER DOWN, KALO.
THESE GUYS
ARE OUR GUESTS.
PICK UP A CUE,
CAPTAIN.
GO AHEAD.
YOU GOT TO
EXCUSE MY BOYS.
YOU CAN'T BE TOO CAREFUL
AROUND HERE THESE DAYS.
YES. JUDGING FROM
WHAT WE'VE SEEN SO FAR,
I AGREE.
THEY CALL YOU THE
BOSS, MR. OKMYX.
THE BOSS OF WHAT?
THE BOSS
OF MY TERRITORY.
I GOT THE BIGGEST
IN THE WORLD.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S
ONE THING WRONG WITH
HAVING THE BIGGEST.
THERE'S ALWAYS SOME PUNK
TRYING TO CUT YOU OUT.
THAT'S WHY YOU
CAN'T BE TOO CAREFUL.
YOU'RE THE GOVERNMENT
HERE?
WHAT GOVERNMENT?
LIKE I TOLD YOU, I
GOT THE TERRITORY,
AND I RUN IT, THAT'S ALL.
BUT THERE
ARE OTHER BOSSES,
OTHER TERRITORIES?
YEAH, SURE.
MAYBE A DOZEN OR SO,
NOT COUNTING
THE SMALL FRY,
BUT THEN THEY
GET BURNED ANYWAY,
AS SOON AS I
GET AROUND TO IT.
DOES THAT INCLUDE,
IF I MAY ASK,
A GENTLEMAN
CALLED KRAKO?
HOW DO YOU KNOW
ABOUT KRAKO?
HE HIT US, BOSS.
O.K.
YOU HIT HIM BACK,
YOU HEAR? HARD.
I'LL HANDLE IT.
CAPTAIN?
DOCTOR.
GANGSTERS.
CHICAGO.
MOBS.
PUBLISHED IN 1992.
WHERE'D YOU GET THIS?
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
THAT'S THE BOOK.
I KNOW IT'S A BOOK.
THE BOOK.
THEY LEFT IT,
THE OTHER SHIP,
THE HORIZON.
THIS IS THE
CONTAMINATION,
CAPTAIN.
ASTONISHING.
AN ENTIRE
CULTURE
BASED ON THIS.
YOU SAID THEY
WERE IMITATIVE
AND THE BOOK--
I DON'T WANT ANY MORE
CRACKS ABOUT THE BOOK.
DID THEY LEAVE
ANY OTHER BOOKS?
YEAH, SURE.
SOME TEXTBOOKS ON HOW
TO MAKE RADIO SETS
AND STUFF LIKE THAT,
BUT LOOK, I BROUGHT YOU
HERE SO YOU COULD HELP ME,
NOT FOR YOU TO
ASK ME QUESTIONS.
AFTER THAT,
I'LL ANSWER ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WELL...
I WAS THINKING.
YOU FEDS MUST HAVE MADE
A LOT OF IMPROVEMENTS
SINCE THAT OTHER
SHIP CAME HERE.
YOU PROBABLY GOT ALL KINDS
OF FANCY HEATERS UP THERE.
SO HERE'S THE DEAL.
YOU GIVE ME ALL
THE HEATERS I NEED--
ENOUGH TOOLS
SO I CAN
KNOCK OFF ALL
THOSE PUNKS ALL AT ONCE.
THEN I'LL TAKE OVER,
THEN ALL YOU HAVE TO
DO IS DEAL WITH ME.
NOW LET ME GET
THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU WANT US
TO SUPPLY YOU
WITH ARMS AND ASSISTANCE
SO YOU CAN CARRY OUT
AN AGGRESSION AGAINST
YOUR NEIGHBORS?
WHAT AGGRESSION?
I GOT TO MAKE SOME HITS.
I WANT YOU TO HELP
ME HIT THEM, THAT'S ALL.
FASCINATING...
BUT QUITE
IMPOSSIBLE.
MR. OKMYX, MY ORDERS
ARE QUITE EXPLICIT.
UNDER NO CIRCUM--
I AIN'T INTERESTED
IN YOUR ORDERS.
FROM NOW ON, YOU'RE GOING
TO TAKE ORDERS FROM ME.
I'M GOING TO GIVE
YOU JUST EIGHT HOURS
TO GIVE ME THE THINGS I WANT.
IF I DON'T HAVE
THOSE TOOLS BY THEN,
I'M GOING TO CALL UP YOUR SHIP
AND HAVE THEM PICK YOU UP--
IN A BOX.
IS THAT
UNDERSTOOD, PAL?
HEY, BOSS,
THIS HERE'S
A HEATER,
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THIS IS.
WELL, LET'S SEE HOW
THIS THING WORKS.
DON'T DO THAT.
YOU COULD
KNOCK OUT THE SIDE
OF THE BUILDING.
THAT GOOD, HUH?
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
GIVE ME ABOUT 100 OF
THESE FANCY HEATERS,
AND WE'LL HAVE
NO MORE TROUBLE.
OUT OF THE QUESTION.
CAPTAIN KIRK, I
USUALLY GET WHAT I WANT.
WHAT'S THIS THING?
ALL RIGHT, BURN 'EM.
NOW, HOLD IT.
IT'S A COMMUNICATION
DEVICE.
HOW DOES IT WORK?
IT'S LOCKED ONTO
MY SHIP'S SYSTEM--
KALO, TAKE THEM
TO THE WAREHOUSE
AND PUT THEM IN A BAG.
KEEP A SHARP EYE
ON THEM, YOU HEAR?
IN THE BAG, BOSS.
COME ON.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
HEY, YOU...
IN THE SHIP UP THERE!
HEY, YOU IN THE SHIP.
SCOTT HERE.
WHO IS THIS?
THIS IS BELA OKMYX.
I GOT YOUR CAPTAIN
AND HIS FRIENDS DOWN HERE.
YOU WANT TO SEE
THEM ALIVE AGAIN,
YOU'LL SEND ME 100
OF THESE FANCY HEATERS
AND SOME TROOPS TO
SHOW ME HOW TO USE THEM.
AM I TO UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU'RE HOLDING THE
CAPTAIN AND HIS PARTY?
YOU HEARD RIGHT, PAL.
I'M GOING TO GIVE
YOU JUST EIGHT HOURS
TO GET ME THE
GOODS I WANT,
OR I PUT THE HIT
ON YOUR FRIENDS.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
I DON'T KNOW.
HEH HEH.
HEH HEH HEH HEH!
LIEUTENANT HADLEY,
CHECK THE LANGUAGE BANKS
AND FIND OUT WHAT A...
HEATER IS.
ONE BOOK ON THE
GANGS OF CHICAGO
DID ALL THIS.
IT'S AMAZING.
THEY EVIDENTLY SEIZED
UPON THAT ONE BOOK
AS THE BLUEPRINT
FOR AN ENTIRE SOCIETY.
AS THE BIBLE.
IN OLD CHICAGO,
CONVENTIONAL GOVERNMENT
ALMOST BROKE DOWN, THE
GANGS NEARLY TOOK OVER.
YEAH, WELL, THIS
OKMYX IS THE WORST
GANGSTER OF ALL.
WE MAY QUARREL
WITH MR. OKMYX' METHODS,
BUT HIS GOAL IS
ESSENTIALLY THE
CORRECT ONE.
THIS SOCIETY
MUST BECOME UNITED,
OR IT WILL DEGENERATE
INTO TOTAL ANARCHY.
IF THIS SOCIETY BROKE DOWN
AS A RESULT OF
THE HORIZON'S INFLUENCE,
THEN THE FEDERATION'S
RESPONSIBLE,
AND WE'VE GOT
TO DO SOMETHING TO
STRAIGHTEN THIS MESS OUT.
SPOCK, IF YOU COULD GET TO
THE SOCIOLOGICAL COMPUTERS,
DO YOU THINK YOU
COULD FIND A SOLUTION?
UNFORTUNATELY,
I DO NOT HAVE ACCESS
TO MY COMPUTERS,
NOR ARE THESE GENTLEMEN
LIKELY TO PERMIT IT.
WELL, I'VE GOT AN
IDEA ABOUT THAT.
GENTLEMEN, GENTLEMEN.
THIS--THIS CARD GAME
IS A KID'S GAME.
YOU THINK SO?
OH, YES. I WOULDN'T
WASTE MY TIME.
WHO'S ASKING YOU?
ON BETA ANTARES 4,
THEY PLAY A REAL GAME.
IT'S A MAN'S GAME,
BUT OF COURSE, IT'S
PROBABLY A
LITTLE BEYOND YOU.
IT REQUIRES
INTELLIGENCE.
LISTEN, KIRK,
I CAN PLAY ANYTHING
YOU CAN FIGURE OUT.
TAKE THE CARDS,
BIG MAN.
SHOW US
HOW IT'S PLAYED.
CAPTAIN, I AM FAMILIAR WITH
THE CULTURE ON BETA ANTARES 4.
I DON'T KNOW--
SPOCK. SPOCK.
OF COURSE, THE CARDS
ON BETA ANTARES 4
ARE DIFFERENT,
BUT NOT TOO DIFFERENT.
THE NAME OF THE
GAME IS CALLED...
FIZZBIN.
FIZZBIN?
FIZZBIN. IT'S...
NOT TOO DIFFICULT.
EACH PLAYER
GETS SIX CARDS,
EXCEPT FOR THE DEALER--
THE PLAYER ON
THE DEALER'S RIGHT,
WHO GETS SEVEN.
ON THE RIGHT?
YES. THE SECOND CARD
IS TURNED UP,
EXCEPT ON TUESDAY.
ON TUESDAY?
[KIRK]
MM-HMM.
OH, LOOK WHAT YOU
GOT, TWO JACKS.
YOU GOT A HALF
FIZZBIN ALREADY.
I NEED ANOTHER JACK.
NO, NO, IF YOU
GOT ANOTHER JACK,
WHY, YOU'D HAVE A SRALK.
A SRALK?
YES, YOU'D
BE DISQUALIFIED.
NO, WHAT YOU NEED
NOW IS EITHER A
KING AND A DEUCE,
EXCEPT AT NIGHT, OF COURSE,
WHEN YOU'D NEED A QUEEN AND A 4.
EXCEPT AT NIGHT.
RIGHT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
YOU'VE GOT ANOTHER JACK!
HA HA HA!
HOW LUCKY YOU ARE!
HOW WONDERFUL FOR YOU.
NOW, IF YOU DIDN'T
GET ANOTHER JACK--
IF YOU HAD GOTTEN A KING,
WHY, THEN, YOU'D
GET ANOTHER CARD,
EXCEPT WHEN IT'S DARK,
WHEN YOU'D HAVE TO GIVE IT BACK.
IF IT WERE DARK
ON TUESDAY.
YES, BUT WHAT YOU'RE
AFTER IS A ROYAL FIZZBIN,
BUT THE ODDS IN
GETTING A ROYAL FIZZBIN
ARE ASTRON--
SPOCK, WHAT ARE THE ODDS
IN GETTING A ROYAL FIZZBIN?
I'VE NEVER COMPUTED
THEM, CAPTAIN.
WELL, THEY'RE ASTRONOMICAL,
BELIEVE ME.
NOW, FOR THE LAST CARD.
WE'LL CALL IT A KRONK.
YOU GOT THAT?
WHAT?
OH, I'LL GET IT.
SPOCK,
FIND THE
RADIO STATION.
UHURA'S MONITORING
THE BROADCASTS.
CUT IN AND HAVE YOURSELVES
BEAMED UP TO THE SHIP.
SURELY, YOU'RE COMING,
CAPTAIN.
I WILL, BUT I'M BRINGING
BELA OKMYX WITH ME.
JIM, YOU CAN'T--
BONES, THIS MESS
IS OUR RESPONSIBILITY.
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
LET'S GO.
[DOG BARKS]
HOLD IT!
O.K., PALLY, WE'RE
GOING FOR A RIDE.
IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D RATHER WALK.
LISTEN, PALLY, THIS
COULD EITHER BE A
TAXI OR A HEARSE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
I'M BEGINNING
TO GET THE IDEA.
YOU DO THAT VERY WELL.
NOW, HOW ARE YOU
WITH PRIMITIVE
RADIO EQUIPMENT?
VERY SIMPLE.
AMPLITUDE MODULATION
TRANSMISSION.
I SIMPLY
ADJUST THE FREQUENCY,
THROW THIS SWITCH.
THE ENTERPRISE
SHOULD ANSWER.
THAT WAS THE JAILBREAKERS
WITH THEIR LATEST RECORDING
ON REQUEST TIME,
BROUGHT TO YOU
BY BANG-BANG,
THE MAKERS OF THE
SWEETEST LITTLE
AUTOMATIC IN THE WORLD--
FASCINATING.
AND VERY SIMPLE?
WELL, LET'S SEE.
ENTERPRISE,
THIS IS MR. SPOCK.
LIEUTENANT UHURA HERE.
MR. SPOCK, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING ON THIS FREQUENCY?
A VERY LONG
AND COMPLICATED
STORY, LIEUTENANT.
NOTIFY THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM--
TWO TO BEAM UP,
THESE COORDINATES.
SO YOU'RE THE FED, HUH?
WELL, WELL,
WELL, WELL, WELL.
AND YOU?
KRAKO! JOJO KRAKO.
I'M THE HEAD OF THE WHOLE
SOUTHSIDE TERRITORY.
HEY, I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
WOULD YOU MIND
TELLING ME HOW YOU
EVEN KNOW WHO I AM?
SIT DOWN, KIRK!
I'VE GOT ALL OF BELA'S
COMMUNICATIONS BUGGED.
HE CAN'T MAKE A
DATE WITH A BROAD
UNLESS I KNOW ABOUT IT.
WELL, I GUESS
YOU WANT TO KNOW...
WHY I BROUGHT YOU HERE.
YOU WANT TO
MAKE A DEAL.
HEY, I LIKE THAT.
THAT IS SHARP.
THAT'S SHARP, EH,
ZABO?
SHARP, BOSS.
THAT'S RIGHT,
A DEAL.
I WANT YOU
TO HELP ME.
UH, LET ME GUESS.
YOU WANT...
YOU WANT HEATERS,
AND THEN YOU'LL WANT,
UM...
TROOPS TO
TEACH THEM HOW
TO USE THEM.
AND, WELL, YOU'LL
ATTACK THE OTHER BOSSES
AND TAKE OVER
THE WHOLE PLANET.
THEN WE'LL SIT DOWN
AND TALK, RIGHT?
WRONG! I KNOW BELA.
HE DIDN'T
OFFER YOU BEANS.
NOW, ME...
I'M A REASONABLE MAN.
YOU GIVE ME
WHAT I WANT,
AND I'LL CUT YOU
IN FOR, SAY, UH...
A THIRD, SKIMMED
RIGHT OFF THE TOP.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I GOT A BETTER IDEA.
THIS PLANET
HAS TO BE UNITED.
NOW, YOU KNOW THAT,
BELA KNOWS THAT.
LET'S, SIT DOWN--
YOU, ME, BELA--
DISCUSS
THIS WHOLE MATTER,
CONTACT
THE OTHER BOSSES,
AND TALK ABOUT IT
LIKE REASONABLE MEN.
YOU WATCH IT, KIRK!
THE BOOK TELLS US
HOW TO HANDLE THINGS!
[SNAPS FINGERS]
YOU MAKE HITS.
SOMEBODY ARGUES,
YOU LEAN ON 'EM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
WE'RE STUPID OR
SOMETHING?
NO, NO, NO, I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE STUPID, MR. KRAKO.
I JUST THINK YOUR
BEHAVIOR IS ARRESTED.
I'VE NEVER BEEN
ARRESTED IN MY
WHOLE LIFE!
NOW, LISTEN, PALLY,
I KNOW HOW TO GET
WHAT I WANT.
YOU WANT TO LIVE?
YOU BET YOU DO.
BUT AFTER I GET
THROUGH WITH YOU,
YOU'RE LIABLE
TO BE SORRY UNLESS
YOU COME ACROSS.
HOLD HIM HERE.
TELL CIRL THE KNIFE
TO SHARPEN UP
HIS BLADE.
I JUST MIGHT
HAVE A JOB FOR HIM.
UNLESS YOU COME ACROSS
WITH THE HEATERS.
I'M SORRY, KRAKO.
NO DEAL.
THAT'S TOO BAD.
PUT HIM ON ICE!
WELL?
FUTILE, DOCTOR.
NO SPECIFICS.
THERE IS NO RECORD
OF SUCH A CULTURE
BASED ON
A MORAL INVERSION.
YOU MEAN
YOU'RE GIVING UP?
NO, DOCTOR.
I'M MERELY SAYING
THE COMPUTERS
CAN OFFER US
NO LOGICAL,
RATIONAL, FACTUAL
WAY OUT
OF OUR CURRENT DILEMMA.
MR. SPOCK,
MR. OKMYX
IS MAKING CONTACT
FROM THE SURFACE.
ON AUDIO,
LIEUTENANT.
MR. OKMYX,
THIS IS MR. SPOCK.
HUH? HEY,
HOW'D YOU GET
BACK UP THERE?
IRRELEVANT,
SINCE WE ARE HERE.
HUH, YEAH.
I TELL YOU, YOU
BETTER COME ON
BACK DOWN.
KRAKO'S PUT THE BAG
ON YOUR CAPTAIN.
WHY WOULD HE
PUT A BAG ON
OUR CAPTAIN?
KIDNAPPED HIM, YA DOPE.
AND HE'LL SCRAG HIM, TOO.
IF I UNDERSTAND
YOU CORRECTLY,
THAT WOULD SEEM
TO BE A PROBLEM.
LOOK, YOU GUYS
GOT SOMETHING I WANT.
I CAN HELP YOU GET
YOUR CAPTAIN BACK.
THEN WE CAN TALK
ABOUT THE DEAL I WANT.
I'M AFRAID I FIND IT
DIFFICULT TO TRUST
YOU, MR. OKMYX.
WHAT'S TO TRUST?
BUSINESS IS BUSINESS.
WE'LL CALL A TRUCE.
YOU COME ON DOWN.
MY BOYS WILL SPRING KIRK,
AND THEN WE'LL TALK
ABOUT GIVING ME A HAND.
YOU WILL SHOW
NO FURTHER
HOSTILITY?
I'M A BUSINESS
MAN, PALLY.
WHAT DO YA SAY?
SINCE WE MUST HAVE
OUR CAPTAIN BACK,
I ACCEPT.
WE SHALL ARRIVE
IN YOUR OFFICE
WITHIN 10 MINUTES.
SPOCK OUT.
YOU MEAN YOU'RE
GOING TO TRUST HIM?
IF WE ARE TO
SAVE THE CAPTAIN
WITHOUT
BLATANT, FORCEFUL
INTERFERENCE
ON THIS PLANET,
DOCTOR,
WE MUST HAVE
THE ASSISTANCE OF
SOMEONE INDIGENOUS.
WE ARE THEREFORE
FORCED TO TRUST
MR. OKMYX.
HELP ME! HELP!
HELP ME!
OH!
MR. SCOTT,
THOUGH WE HOPE
TO AVOID INTERFERENCE,
I SUGGEST YOU SET
ONE OF OUR PHASER BANKS
ON A STRONG STUN
POSITION.
AYE, SIR.
NOW YOU'RE BEGINNING
TO MAKE SENSE.
I TRUST WE SHALL
NOT HAVE TO
USE THEM,
BUT IT IS BEST
TO BE PREPARED.
ENERGIZE.
YOU KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
DON'T WORRY,
BOSS.
THEY CAN'T
DO NOTHING
TILL THEY'RE
THROUGH
SPARKLING.
JUST THE SAME,
YOU BE CAREFUL.
THEY'LL HAVE
HEATERS ON THEM.
NOW YOU WATCH THIS.
SHIP'S LOG.
MR. SPOCK REPORTING.
INCREDIBLE AS IT SEEMS,
DR. McCOY AND I
ARE ONCE AGAIN PRISONERS
OF THE CHIEF
CRIMINAL BOSS
OF A SOCIETY PATTERNED
AFTER OLD EARTH GANGSTERS.
PICK UP MANY
MORE OF THESE,
I WON'T NEED
YOUR COOPERATION.
MR. OKMYX,
I UNDERSTOOD WE HAD
AN ARRANGEMENT,
A TRUCE.
I WAS HOPING
YOU'D THINK
THAT, DUMMY.
WE'RE TRYING
TO HELP YOU, OKMYX!
NOBODY HELPS
NOBODY BUT HIMSELF.
SIR, YOU ARE EMPLOYING
A DOUBLE NEGATIVE.
HUH?
I FAIL TO SEE
WHY YOU DO NOT
UNDERSTAND US.
YOU YOURSELF HAVE
STATED THE NEED
FOR UNITY OF
AUTHORITY ON THIS
PLANET. WE AGREE.
YEAH, BUT I GOTTA
BE THE UNITY.
COOPERATION, SIR,
WOULD INEVITABLY
RESULT--
THE MOST COOPERATIVE
MAN IN THIS WORLD
IS A DEAD MAN.
AND IF YOU DON'T
KEEP YOUR MOUTH SHUT,
YOU'RE GOING TO
BE COOPERATIN'.
DROP THE GUNS.
DROP 'EM.
MOVE DOWN THERE.
HEY, CAPTAIN,
YOU GOT AWAY
FROM KRAKO.
YOU KNOW,
THAT AIN'T EASY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
SUPPOSED TO REPORT
TO THE SHIP,
MR. SPOCK.
WE DID, CAPTAIN.
THE SITUATION
REQUIRED OUR RETURN.
IT MAY BE
JUST AS WELL.
DID YOU FIND OUT
ANYTHING FROM
THE COMPUTER?
NOTHING USEFUL.
LOGIC AND PRACTICAL
INFORMATION DO NOT
SEEM TO APPLY HERE.
YOU ADMIT THAT?
TO DENY THE FACTS
WOULD BE ILLOGICAL,
DOCTOR.
THEN YOU DON'T MIND
IF I PLAY A HUNCH?
I'M NOT SANGUINE
ABOUT HUNCHES,
CAPTAIN,
BUT I HAVE
NO PRACTICAL
ALTERNATIVE.
WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO DO NOW, JIM?
WELL, NOW THAT
WE HAVE BELA,
I'M GOING TO PUT
THE BAG ON KRAKO.
LISTEN, YOU...
SAY, THAT'S NICE
MATERIAL.
IT OUGHTA BE.
IT COST
A BUNDLE.
GET OUT OF THEM.
HEY!
JUST A MINUTE!
I SAID--YOU TOO!
GET OUT OF
THE CLOTHES!
NOBODY'S GOING
TO PUT THE BAG
ON ME ANYMORE!
[CAR HORN BEEPS]
WHEELS, MR. SPOCK.
A FLIVVER, CAPTAIN.
KEY IN THE IGNITION.
TURN THE IGNITION ON...
AND NOTHING HAPPENS.
WHERE'S THE STARTER?
THERE'S THE STARTER.
[ENGINE STARTS]
YES!
INTERESTING.
[GRINDING]
OOPS!
GEARS.
YES. OH...
I BELIEVE
THEY HAD A DEVICE
KNOWN AS A...CLUTCH.
CLUTCH, CAPTAIN.
PERHAPS ONE OF THOSE
PEDALS ON THE FLOOR.
I KIND OF LIKE THIS.
I MAY GET
ONE MYSELF.
[CRASH]
[BACKFIRING]
[CAR HORN BEEPS]
CAPTAIN, YOU ARE
AN EXCELLENT STARSHIP
COMMANDER.
BUT AS A TAXI DRIVER,
YOU LEAVE MUCH
TO BE DESIRED.
IT WAS THAT BAD?
NOW, THAT COULD BE
A...BIT OF A PROBLEM.
IF THEY WERE INSIDE,
WHERE THEY WOULDN'T
BE SEEN,
WE COULD STUN THEM
WITH OUR PHASERS,
BUT NOT OUT HERE.
IF WE CAN GET CLOSE
ENOUGH TO THEM,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO RENDER THEM HARMLESS
WITH REASONABLE RAPIDITY.
[BABY CRIES]
THEY DON'T LOOK
LIKE THE TRUSTING
TYPES.
IT'S A HIT,
AIN'T IT?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
YOU'RE GOING TO
HIT SOMEBODY.
CAN I WATCH?
YOUNG MAN,
RUN ALONG AND PLAY.
WHERE'D YOU GET
THEM EARS?
YOUNG MAN...
YOU'RE GOING TO
HIT KRAKO, OUT
HERE?
YOU OPEN UP,
AND YOU'LL BE
SCRABBED
FROM
EVERY WINDOW
IN THE STREET.
I CAN FIX
IT FOR YA.
YOUNG MAN,
THIS IS LIKELY TO BE
QUITE HAZARDOUS.
HOLD ON, SPOCK.
OUT OF THE MOUTHS
OF BABES--
WHO YOU CALLIN'
A BABE?
I'M CALLIN'
YOU A BABE.
YOU CALLIN'
ME A BABE?
YEAH, I'M CALLIN'...
I'M CALLING YOU
A BABE,
BUT THERE'S
NOTHING PERSONAL.
SIT DOWN.
DO YOU KNOW A WAY
WE CAN GET CLOSE
TO THEM?
SURE.
HOW?
WHAT'S IN
IT FOR ME?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
A PIECE OF
THE ACTION.
YOU DO NOT EVEN KNOW
WHAT THE ACTION
IS GOING TO BE.
I FIGURE IT'S GOT
TO BE A THICK
PERCENTAGE,
OR YOU WOULDN'T
BE TRYING TO HIT
KRAKO.
LOGICAL.
ALL RIGHT, YOUNG MAN.
WE'LL GUARANTEE YOU...
A PIECE OF THE ACTION
IF WE CAN PULL
THIS THING OFF.
IS THAT
A CONTRACT?
DONE.
WHAT DO WE DO?
YOU'LL KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
AND THAT!
AND HOW DO YOU
LIKE THAT?
AND THAT?
THINK
YOU CAN GANG UP
ON ME, HUH?
WHAT ARE YOU,
CHICKEN?
COME ON, WHY DON'T
YOU GANG UP ON ME?
I'LL CUT OFF
YOUR HEAD AND THROW
IT IN YOUR FACE!
ALL RIGHT, TAKE
THAT, AND THAT, AND THAT!
AND HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?
AND--DADDY, DADDY,
I HURT MYSELF!
THAT'S IT. LET'S GO.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
DID YOU HURT
YOURSELF, KID?
I WANT MY DADDY!
HE'S A CUTE
KID, AIN'T HE?
I WANT MY DADDY!
SONNY!
I WANT MY DADDY.
SONNY! WAIT A MOMENT.
WHAT HAVE THEY DONE?
WHAT HAVE THEY
DONE TO YOU?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
A PIECE
OF THE ACTION.
NO ONE CAN SEE.
PUT YOUR PHASER
ON STUN.
WELL!
AIN'T THIS NICE?
I WAS WONDERING HOW
I WAS GOING TO
GET YOU BACK,
AND HERE YOU
DELIVER YOURSELVES!
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND
WITH THE EARS, KIRK?
I THINK YOU'VE
GOT IT REVERSED,
MR. KRAKO.
NAW, I AIN'T, PALLY.
PUT DOWN YOUR HEATERS.
[CLICKING]
CAPTAIN, I BELIEVE
THAT PERHAPS
IT WOULD BE WISE
TO DO AS HE SAYS.
I JUST HEARD
THE SOUND OF--
THE SOUND OF
A MACHINE GUN BOLT
BEING PULLED BACK.
MR. KRAKO,
I DON'T, UH..
SO THIS IS THE FANCY
HEATER, HUH?
HOW DOES IT WORK?
I'M TRYING
TO TELL YOU,
MR. KRAKO,
THAT THIS IS BIGGER
THAN YOU, OKMYX,
OR ANYONE.
THE ONLY THING
I WANT YOU TO TELL ME
IS HOW IT WORKS.
CAN YOU TRUST
ALL YOUR MEN?
OF COURSE I CAN!
WELL, ONE OF THESE
CAN MAKE A MAN A PRETTY
BIG BOSS, YOU KNOW.
I EITHER TRUST 'EM,
OR THEY'RE DEAD.
LET'S GO IN HERE
AND TALK ABOUT IT.
NOW WE GOT
NO BUSY LITTLE EYES
TO WORRY ABOUT.
HOW DOES THIS
THING WORK?
ALL RIGHT, KRAKO,
WE DON'T HAVE TIME
TO SHOW YOU HOW TO
PLAY WITH TOYS!
TOYS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
WE'RE HERE FOR,
TO GET A CUT
OF YOUR DEAL?
FORGET IT! THAT'S...
PEANUTS TO AN OUTFIT
LIKE THE FEDERATION.
RIGHT?
UNQUESTIONABLY.
RIGHT.
NOW, LOOK, KRAKO,
WE'RE TAKIN' OVER
THE WHOLE BALL OF WAX.
NOW, YOU COOPERATE WITH US,
AND MAYBE WE'LL
CUT YOU IN FOR
A PIECE OF THE ACTION.
A MINUSCULE...
VERY SMALL PIECE.
HOW MUCH
IS THAT?
THAT'S, UM...
WE'LL FIGURE
IT OUT LATER.
I THOUGHT YOU
GUYS HAD LAWS,
NO INTERFERENCE.
WHO'S INTERFERIN'?
WE'RE TAKIN' OVER.
CHECK?
RIGHT.
THE, UH, PLANET...
IS BEING TAKEN OVER
BY THE FEDERATION,
BUT WE DON'T WANNA
COME IN HERE AND, UH,
USE OUR MUSCLE.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THAT AIN'T, UH, SUBTLE.
SO WHAT WE DO
IS WE HELP ONE GUY
TAKE OVER THE PLANET.
HE PULLS THE STRINGS,
AND THEN WE PULL HIS.
HEH, HEH, HEH, HEH.
HEY, YOU, UM...
SIT DOWN.
WHAT'S YOUR CUT?
WHAT DO YOU CARE,
AS LONG AS YOU'RE
BEING CUT IN?
COURSE, THERE'S
ALWAYS BELA OKMYX.
ALL RIGHT,
IT'S A DEAL.
CALL YOUR SHIP,
BRING DOWN YOUR BOYS
AND WHATEVER ELSE
YOU NEED.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
WE MADE A DEAL WITH KRAKO.
WE DID, SIR?
YEAH. WE'RE READY
TO MAKE THE HIT.
WE'RE TAKIN' OVER
THE WHOLE PLANET, AS
SOON AS YOU GET READY.
DO YOU THINK
THAT'S WISE, SIR?
SURE! WE CAN TRUST KRAKO,
BUT WE DON'T
HAVE ANY CHOICE,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
HE'S STANDIN' ABOUT
12 FEET IN FRONT OF ME,
ALL READY
TO BE OUR PAL.
OF COURSE, SCOTTY, I'D LIKE
TO SHOW HIM THE SHIP
JUST TO SHOW HIM
THAT WE'RE--
WE'RE ON THE LEVEL.
BUT YOU KNOW
HOW IT IS.
AYE.
I KNOW INDEED.
SCOTTY, WE'LL NEED PHASERS
TO EQUIP EVERY ONE
OF KRAKO'S MEN.
WE'LL NEED ADVISORS
AND TROOPS
TO BACK HIM UP
ON THE HIT.
YOU GOT ALL
THAT, SCOTTY?
AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE PREPARING EVERYTHING.
IT'LL BE READY
WHEN YOU GIVE THE WORD.
YOU MAY BEGIN,
MR. SCOTT.
ACKNOWLEDGED, CAPTAIN.
YOU MEAN YOU'RE GOING
TO START SENDING DOWN
YOUR BOYS NOW?
NOT EXACTLY.
RIGHT?
CHECK.
HOW--HOW DID
I GET HERE?
WHAT--WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU--YOU MUST BE THAT
SCOTT FELLOW THAT KIRK
WAS TALKING TO.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED!
IT LOOKS LIKE WE
PUT THE BAG ON
YOU, DOESN'T IT?
I GOT RIGHTS!
YOU GOT NOTHING.
YOU MIND YOUR
PLACE, MISTER,
OR YOU'LL--YOU'LL BE
WEARING CONCRETE GALOSHES.
YOU MEAN CEMENT
OVERSHOES?
UM...AYE.
[CAR HORN BEEPS]
MUST WE?
IT'S FASTER
THAN WALKING.
BUT NOT AS SAFE.
ARE YOU AFRAID
OF CARS?
NOT AT ALL, CAPTAIN.
IT'S YOUR DRIVING
THAT ALARMS ME.
SPOCK, I'VE GOT THE
HANG OF IT, NOW, GO ON.
OH, NOT AGAIN.
HEY, WAKE UP.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
HEY, YOU GUYS,
COME IN HERE!
THE FEDS
SNATCHED KRAKO.
I NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE IT.
THEY'RE GOING
TO MOVE IN
UNLESS WE
STOP 'EM NOW.
YEAH? HOW?
BELA'S MIXED UP
IN THIS SOMEHOW.
I GOT A SNEAKING HUNCH
THEY'RE GOING
TO HIGH-TAIL IT
BACK TO HIS TERRITORY.
YOU KNOW WHAT
WE'RE GOING TO DO?
WE'RE GOING
TO HIT HIS PLACE.
WHERE ARE THEY?
[CHUCKLING]
KNOWING KRAKO,
HE'LL PROBABLY
SEND THEM BACK
ON A BLOTTER.
WRONG AGAIN, OKMYX.
JIM--
KNOCK IT OFF,
SAWBONES.
I WANT TO TALK
TO THIS CREEP.
NOW, LISTEN, I'M GETTING
TIRED OF PLAYING PATTY-CAKE
WITH YOU PENNY
ANTE OPERATORS.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, A
PENNY ANTE OPERATOR?
YOU'RE A PENNY ANTE
OPERATOR! SIT DOWN!
ALL RIGHT, SPOCKO,
COVER HIM.
NOW, LISTEN, SWEETHEART,
THE FEDERATION'S MOVING IN.
WE'RE TAKING OVER.
YOU PLAY BALL,
WE'LL CUT YOU IN
FOR A PIECE OF THE PIE.
YOU DON'T, YOU'RE OUT.
ALL THE WAY OUT,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YEAH, SURE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
ALL YOU HAD TO DO
WAS EXPLAIN IT TO ME.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
YOU GOT KRAKO ON ICE?
AYE, HE'S HERE.
MAD ENOUGH TO CHEW NEUTRONIUM,
BUT BEHAVING HIMSELF.
O.K., BABY, COOL HIM
UNTIL I FLAG YOU.
FLAG ME?
KEEP HIM THERE
UNTIL I SEND FOR HIM.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE SOME
OLD-STYLE PHONE CALLS
FROM THIS LOCALE,
SO YOU LOCATE THE MAN
ON THE OTHER END
OF THE BLOWER
AND GIVE HIM A
RIDE TO THIS FLOP.
WHAT?
FIND THE MAN
AT THE OTHER END
OF THE PHONE
AND TRANSPORT HIM
TO THESE COORDINATES.
CAN DO, SWEETHEART?
CAN DO, CAPTAIN.
STANDING BY.
NOW, YOU...
GET ON THE BLOWER
AND CALL
THE OTHER BOSSES.
I SURE DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
GET WITH IT.
I'M GIVING
THE ORDERS HERE.
[RING]
HELLO. HELLO?
Scotty?
Scott here.
GUESS WHO?
Lock in
and energize.
YEAH, YOU BET YOUR LIFE,
I'VE GOT A LOT OF NERVE.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO ABOUT IT?
COMING OVER THERE WITH A
COUPLE OF MY BOYS AND
WE--
[WHIMPERS]
MOTHER.
HEY, CAPTAIN,
THAT AIN'T BAD.
YEAH.
I WOULD ADVISE YOUSE
TO KEEP DIALING, OKMYX.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE HIT BELA'S PLACE,
AND NOBODY
COMES OUT ALIVE.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO!
[EVERYBODY GRUMBLING]
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT!
NOW, THE FEDERATION'S
TAKING OVER,
WHETHER YOU
LIKE IT OR NOT.
YOU PEOPLE, YOU'VE BEEN
RUNNING THIS PLANET
LIKE A PIECEWORK FACTORY.
FROM NOW ON, IT'S GOING
TO BE UNDER ONE ROOF.
YOU'RE GOING TO RUN
IT LIKE A--LIKE A BUSINESS.
AND THAT MEANS YOU'RE
GOING TO MAKE A PROFIT.
AND WHAT'S
YOUR PERCENTAGE?
I'M CUTTING THE
FEDERATION IN FOR 40%.
YOU GOT ANY OBJECTIONS?
YEAH!
I HEAR A LOT OF TALK,
BUT ALL I SEE HERE
IS YOU AND A COUPLE
OF YOUR BOYS.
I DON'T SEE
NO FEDERATION.
LISTEN!
THEY GOT A SHIP.
I KNOW, I WAS THERE!
WAIT A MINUTE.
TEPO'S GOT A POINT.
ALL WE EVER SEEN
IS THEM.
WHAT--A COUPLE
OF YOUR BOYS?
[EVERYBODY GRUMBLING]
HANG ON A MINUTE.
HANG ON A MINUTE!
QUIET!
JUST A MOMENT!
LET ME SAY SOMETHING.
I ONLY SAW THREE
GUYS IN THAT SHIP.
MAYBE THERE
AIN'T NO MORE.
THERE ARE OVER
400 GUYS THERE.
THAT'S YOUR
STORY, BUSTER.
[BRAKES SCREECH]
[GUNFIRE]
HEY, IT'S MY BOYS.
THEY'RE MAKING A
HIT AT THIS PLACE.
MY BOYS
WILL PUT YOU DOWN.
WANT TO BET?
KEEP MOVING.
ONE MOVE OUT OF
YOU TWO GUYS, AND
I'LL DRILL HIM.
GIVE ME
THE HARDWARE.
HEY, THAT'S
GREAT, KRAKO.
NOW WE GOT HOSTAGES AGAIN.
WE CAN MAKE A DEAL
WITH THE FEDS UP THERE.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
THIS ONE'S ALL MINE.
FROM NOW ON, NOBODY'S
GOING NO PLACE.
I'M GOING TO BE
THE BIG BOSS IN
THIS HERE TERRITORY.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE!
GET THAT HEATER DOWN!
DON'T YOU WANT
TO TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT
YOU'RE GOING TO FIGHT?
I ALREADY SEEN IT.
YOU'RE NOTHING, FED.
ALL RIGHT, BUT AT LEAST
LET ME CALL MY SHIP ONE
LAST TIME AND SAY GOODBYE.
WELL, ALL RIGHT.
GO AHEAD.
DON'T GET SMART.
HELLO, SCOTTY.
THIS IS KIRK.
ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
SCOTTY, PUT THE
SHIP'S PHASERS ON STUN.
FIRE A BURST
IN A ONE-BLOCK RADIUS
AROUND THESE COORDINATES.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
SCOTT OUT.
GEE, THAT'S SOME TRICK.
HEY, DID YOU SEE THAT?
THEY'RE NOT DEAD,
JUST KNOCKED OUT
FOR A WHILE.
BUT THEY MIGHT JUST
AS WELL HAVE BEEN THAT
WAY IF WE WANTED THEM TO.
OK, OK, KIRK,
SO WE GET THE MESSAGE.
NOW, WHAT WAS THIS
SYNDICATE DEAL YOU
WERE TALKING ABOUT?
HE WAS TALKING
ABOUT A PERCENTAGE.
I WAS TALKING
ABOUT BOTH.
OK.
A SYNDICATE
MAKES SENSE TO ME.
I'M A PEACEFUL
MAN AT HEART,
BUT I'M SICK AND TIRED
OF ALL THESE HITS.
I HIT KRAKO.
KRAKO HITS TEPO.
TEPO HITS ME.
THERE'S TOO MANY BOSSES.
WE CAN'T GET
ANYTHING DONE.
I WAS THINKING,
IF THERE WAS JUST ONE--
MAYBE SOMEBODY LIKE
YOU AS THE TOP BOSS--
THEN WE CAN GET
THINGS DONE.
HEY, BELA,
NO, NO, NO.
THE FEDERATION
CAN'T GET CONNECTED
WITH A SMALLTIME
OPERATION LIKE THIS.
NO, I WAS THINKING,
BELA, YOU WOULD BE
THE TOP BOSS.
KRAKO, YOU'D BE
HIS LIEUTENANT.
THE REST OF YOU--
I DON'T WANT ANY
TROUBLE FROM THE
REST OF YOU...
BECAUSE YOU'LL
HAVE TO ANSWER
TO THE FEDERATION.
WE'LL BE BACK
EVERY YEAR TO
COLLECT OUR CUT.
AND LOOK, YOU
FIGURE MAYBE
40% IS ENOUGH?
YEAH, I THINK
40% IS SUFFICIENT.
IT'S REASONABLE.
IT SOUNDS REASONABLE.
THAT SOUND
REASONABLE TO YOU?
IT'S REASONABLE,
MR. OKMYX.
LET'S BREAK
OUT SOME OF YOUR
DRINKING STUFF...
[GLASSES CLINK]
AND CELEBRATE
THE SYNDICATE.
GENTLEMEN, YOU TWO
HAVE BEEN BROODING
EVER SINCE
WE RETURNED
TO THE SHIP.
BROODING, CAPTAIN?
BROODING, MR. SPOCK,
A SOMBER EMOTIONAL STATE.
NOW, DO YOU WISH TO
CONTINUE IT, OR ARE YOU
GOING TO DISCUSS IT?
CAPTAIN, I'M NEITHER
BROODING NOR SOMBER.
BUT I DO
HAVE RESERVATIONS
ABOUT YOUR SOLUTION
TO THE PROBLEM
OF THE IOTIANS.
AH, YES.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
YOU DON'T THINK
IT'S LOGICAL
TO LEAVE A CRIMINAL
ORGANIZATION IN
CHARGE.
HIGHLY IRREGULAR,
TO SAY THE LEAST, CAPTAIN.
I'M ALSO CURIOUS
AS TO HOW YOU
PROPOSE TO EXPLAIN
TO STARFLEET COMMAND
THAT A STARSHIP
WILL BE SENT EACH YEAR
TO COLLECT OUR "CUT."
YES, THAT'S A VERY
GOOD QUESTION, MR. SPOCK.
I PROPOSE THAT OUR
CUT BE PUT INTO THE
PLANETARY TREASURY
AND USED TO GUIDE
THE IOTIANS INTO
A MORE ETHICAL SYSTEM.
DESPITE THEMSELVES,
THEY'LL BE FORCED
TO ACCEPT CONVENTIONAL
RESPONSIBILITIES.
ISN'T THAT LOGICAL?
ALL RIGHT, BONES,
IN THE LANGUAGE
OF THE PLANET,
WHAT'S YOUR BEEF?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW HOW
SERIOUS THIS IS, JIM.
AND I DON'T QUITE
KNOW HOW TO TELL YOU.
WELL, GO AHEAD.
BUT IN ALL THE
CONFUSION, I...
TELL ME.
I THINK I LEFT IT
IN BELA'S OFFICE.
YOU LEFT IT?
SOMEWHERE.
I'M NOT CERTAIN.
YOU'RE NOT
CERTAIN OF WHAT?
I LEFT MY COMMUNICATOR.
IN BELA'S OFFICE?
CAPTAIN, IF THE IOTIANS,
WHO ARE VERY BRIGHT
AND IMITATIVE PEOPLE,
SHOULD TAKE THAT
COMMUNICATOR APART--
THEY WILL, THEY WILL,
AND THEY'LL FIND OUT
HOW THE TRANSTATOR WORKS.
THE TRANSTATOR
IS THE BASIS
FOR EVERY IMPORTANT
PIECE OF EQUIPMENT
THAT WE HAVE.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
IT'S THAT SERIOUS?
SERIOUS? SERIOUS, BONES?
IT UPSETS THE
WHOLE PERCENTAGE.
HOW DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, IN A FEW YEARS,
THE IOTIANS MAY DEMAND
A PIECE OF OUR ACTION.