CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4307.1.
APPROACHING STARBASE 6
FOR A MUCH NEEDED PERIOD
OF REST AND RECREATION.
THIS CREW HAS PERFORMED
EXCELLENTLY,
BUT IS EXHAUSTED.
AND I, TOO,
AM LOOKING FORWARD
TO A NICE PERIOD OF REST
ON SOME LOVELY PLANET.
CAPTAIN.
THERE WAS A MESSAGE
FROM STARBASE 6.
HEAVY INTERFERENCE.
ALL I GET IS INTREPID
AND WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
A SECTOR COORDINATE.
INTERESTING.
NO INDICATIONS OF MAGNETIC
STORMS IN THIS SECTOR.
TRY ANOTHER CHANNEL,
LIEUTENANT.
AYE, SIR.
INTREPID IS MANNED
BY VULCANS,
ISN'T IT?
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
ENTERPRISE
CALLING STARBASE 6.
COME IN. COME IN.
SPOCK?
WHAT IS IT, SPOCK?
ARE YOU IN PAIN?
CAPTAIN...
THE INTREPID...
IT JUST...DIED.
AND THE 400 VULCANS
ABOARD...
ALL DEAD.
COME ON, SPOCK.
LET'S GO DOWN TO SICK BAY.
DOCTOR, I KNOW WHAT I KNOW.
GET TO THE
SICK BAY.
CAPTAIN...
NO, NO, NO.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE
STARBASE 6 READABLE NOW.
SWITCHING TO AUDIO, SIR.
KIRK HERE. GO AHEAD.
WILL DIVERT
IMMEDIATELY
TO SECTOR 39J.
SIR, THE ENTERPRISE
JUST COMPLETED
AN EXHAUSTING MISSION.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY IN
FOR R AND R.
THERE MUST BE
ANOTHER STARSHIP
IN THAT SECTOR.
NEGATIVE. THIS IS
A RESCUE PRIORITY.
WE'VE LOST ALL CONTACT
WITH SOLAR SYSTEM GAMMA 7A,
WHICH THE INTREPID
WAS INVESTIGATING,
AND WE'VE JUST LOST CONTACT
WITH THE INTREPID.
REPORT PROGRESS.
ORDER ACKNOWLEDGED.
KIRK OUT.
MR. KYLE,
YOU HEARD THE ORDER.
SET A COURSE FOR GAMMA 7A,
WARP 5.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN...
I HAVE JUST COMPLETED
A FULL LONG-RANGE SCAN
OF GAMMA 7A SYSTEM.
IT IS DEAD.
DEAD?
THAT WAS
A FOURTH MAGNITUDE SUN.
THERE ARE BILLIONS
OF INHABITANTS THERE.
IT IS DEAD.
Captain Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
I ASSURE YOU, DOCTOR,
I'M QUITE ALL RIGHT.
THE PAIN WAS MOMENTARY.
IT PASSED QUICKLY.
ALL OF MY INSTRUMENTS
SEEM TO AGREE WITH YOU,
IF I CAN TRUST THESE
CRAZY VULCAN READINGS.
SPOCK, HOW CAN YOU
BE SO SURE THE INTREPID
WAS DESTROYED?
I SENSED IT DIE.
BUT I THOUGHT YOU
HAD TO BE IN
PHYSICAL CONTACT
WITH A SUBJECT
BEFORE--
DOCTOR, EVEN I,
A HALF VULCAN,
COULD HEAR THE DEATH SCREAM
OF 400 VULCAN MINDS
CRYING OUT OVER
THE DISTANCE BETWEEN US.
NOT EVEN A VULCAN
COULD FEEL
A STARSHIP DIE.
CALL IT
A DEEP UNDERSTANDING
OF THE WAY THINGS
HAPPEN TO VULCANS,
BUT I KNOW
THAT NOT A PERSON,
NOT EVEN THE COMPUTERS
ON BOARD THE INTREPID,
KNEW WHAT
WAS KILLING THEM
OR WOULD HAVE UNDERSTOOD IT
HAD THEY KNOWN.
BUT 400 VULCANS.
I'VE NOTICED THAT
ABOUT YOUR PEOPLE,
DOCTOR.
YOU FIND IT EASIER
TO UNDERSTAND
THE DEATH OF ONE
THAN THE DEATH
OF A MILLION.
YOU SPEAK ABOUT
THE OBJECTIVE HARDNESS
OF THE VULCAN HEART,
YET HOW LITTLE ROOM
THERE SEEMS TO BE IN YOURS.
SUFFER THE DEATH
OF THY NEIGHBOR, EH, SPOCK?
YOU WOULDN'T WISH THAT
ON US, WOULD YOU?
IT MIGHT HAVE RENDERED
YOUR HISTORY
A BIT LESS BLOODY.
SPOCK, YOU MAY
HAVE BEEN RIGHT.
WE'VE JUST LOST CONTACT
WITH THE INTREPID
AND ARE OUT OF COMMUNICATION
WITH AN ENTIRE SOLAR SYSTEM.
ANY UPDATE FROM STARFLEET?
I CANNOT FILTER OUT
THE DISTORTION, SIR.
IT'S GETTING WORSE.
CAPTAIN, DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
JUST SNAPPED ON.
SLOW TO WARP 3.
WARP 3, SIR.
INDICATIONS OF ENERGY
TURBULENCE AHEAD.
UNABLE TO ANALYZE.
I'VE NEVER ENCOUNTERED
READINGS LIKE THIS BEFORE.
SCANNERS ON.
MAGNIFICATION 3
ON THE SCREEN.
MAGNIFICATION
FACTOR 3, SIR.
EXACTLY WHAT ARE WE
LOOKING FOR, MR. SPOCK?
I WOULD ASSUME...
THAT.
WHAT IS THAT?
PERHAPS AN INTERSTELLAR
DUST CLOUD.
NOT VERY LIKELY, ENSIGN.
NO. YOU WOULD
BE ABLE TO SEE STARS
THROUGH A DUST CLOUD.
LOOKS LIKE
A HOLE IN SPACE.
READINGS, MR. SPOCK.
STILL NOT ABLE TO ANALYZE,
CAPTAIN.
SENSORS ARE FEEDING DATA
TO THE COMPUTERS NOW.
WHATEVER THIS DARK ZONE IS,
IT LIES DIRECTLY IN LINE
WITH THE COURSE I CALCULATE
FOR THE INTREPID
AND THE GAMMA 7A SYSTEM.
HOLD PRESENT COURSE.
SLOW TO WARP 1.
WARP FACTOR 1, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, PREPARE
TO LAUNCH TELEMETRY PROBE
INTO THAT ZONE.
DIRECT COMPUTER FEED
TO MR. SPOCK.
AYE, SIR. PROBE READY.
SWITCHING DATA FEED
TO LIBRARY COMPUTER.
LAUNCH PROBE.
PROBE LAUNCHED, SIR.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
WHAT WAS THAT?
THE TELEMETRY PROBE,
SIR.
THERE'S NO SIGNAL
FROM IT NOW.
SPECULATION, SPOCK.
I HAVE NONE, CAPTAIN.
INSUFFICIENT DATA.
[GROAN]
OHH!
LIEUTENANT.
I'M JUST DIZZY.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I'M FINE, SIR.
SICK BAY
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
McCOY HERE.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT?
I'M GETTING REPORTS
FROM EVERY DECK.
HALF THE PEOPLE
ON THIS SHIP
JUST FAINTED.
UHURA ALMOST DID.
SHE SAYS SHE'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU WANT TO SEE HER?
NOT UNLESS
SHE'S FEELING ILL.
I'VE GOT AN
EMERGENCY DOWN HERE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
WELL, THERE'S
NOTHING ORGANIC.
THEY ALL SEEM
TO BE NERVOUS, WEAK,
AND IRRITABLE.
THEY SAY IT HAPPENED
SUDDENLY, LIKE A
BALLOON POPPING.
CAN YOU HANDLE IT, BONES?
I'M GIVING THEM
STIMULANTS
TO KEEP THEM
ON THEIR FEET.
YEAH, WE CAN HANDLE
IT, JIM.
GOOD. KIRK OUT.
HOLD OUR POSITION,
MR. KYLE.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
SPOCK, GIVE ME AN UPDATE
ON THE DARK AREA AHEAD.
NO ANALYSIS DUE TO
INSUFFICIENT INFORMATION.
NO SPECULATION,
NO INFORMATION,
NOTHING.
I'VE ASKED YOU 3 TIMES
FOR INFORMATION
ON THAT THING,
AND YOU'VE BEEN UNABLE
TO SUPPLY IT.
"INSUFFICIENT DATA"
IS NOT SUFFICIENT,
MR. SPOCK.
YOU'RE
THE SCIENCE OFFICER.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO
HAVE SUFFICIENT DATA
ALL THE TIME.
I'M WELL AWARE OF THAT,
CAPTAIN,
BUT THE COMPUTERS CONTAIN
NOTHING ON THIS PHENOMENON.
IT IS BEYOND OUR EXPERIENCE,
AND THE NEW INFORMATION
IS NOT YET SIGNIFICANT.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I'M TIRED.
IF YOU CAN'T TELL ME
WHAT IT IS,
LET'S USE REVERSE LOGIC.
PERHAPS IT'LL HELP
IF YOU TELL ME
WHAT IT ISN'T.
IT IS NOT LIQUID,
GASEOUS, OR SOLID,
DESPITE THE FACT
WE CANNOT SEE THROUGH IT.
SO FAR THAT'S NOT
MUCH HELP.
IT IS NOT A GALACTIC NEBULA
SUCH AS THE COAL SACK,
AND SINCE OUR DEFLECTORS
WERE ACTIVATED BY IT,
IT WOULD SEEM TO BE
SOME FORM OF ENERGY,
BUT NOTHING OUR SENSORS
CAN IDENTIFY.
IS IT POSSIBLE...
THAT THIS IS WHAT
KILLED THAT SOLAR SYSTEM
AND THE INTREPID?
VERY POSSIBLE.
LIEUTENANT.
YES, SIR.
NOTIFY THE STARFLEET...
THAT WE'RE GOING
TO ATTEMPT TO PROBE
THE AREA OF DARKNESS
TO GAIN FURTHER INFORMATION.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN?
DISTANCE FROM ZONE
OF DARKNESS, MR. KYLE?
100,000 KILOMETERS, SIR.
AHEAD SLOW.
IMPULSE POWER OFF.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
TRANSMISSION TO STARFLEET
COMPLETE, SIR.
VERY GOOD.
TIME, MR. CHEKOV.
PENETRATION OF THE ZONE
IN ONE MINUTE,
SEVEN SECONDS, SIR.
RED ALERT.
DEFLECTORS FULL POWER.
PHASER BANKS READY.
PHASERS STANDING BY.
DEFLECTORS
AT FULL POWER, SIR.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
IT'S NOT COMING
FROM COMMUNICATIONS, SIR.
SPOCK!
ANALYZING NOW, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN...
THE STARS...
ARE GONE!
MALFUNCTION, MR. SPOCK?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
ALL SYSTEMS
FUNCTIONING PROPERLY.
THEN KINDLY TELL
ME WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE STARS.
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO McCOY.
McCOY HERE.
THINGS ANY BETTER
DOWN THERE?
WORSE. THEY'RE BACKED
UP INTO THE CORRIDOR.
HAVE YOU GOT ANYTHING
THAT WILL HELP UP HERE?
I DON'T WANT ANYBODY
FOLDING ON THE BRIDGE
AT A CRITICAL MOMENT.
ON MY WAY.
McCOY OUT.
KIRK TO ENGINEERING.
SCOTTY, THERE
WAS A POWER LOSS.
HOW COME?
WE LOST 5% OF OUR
ENERGY RESERVE, SIR.
OUR DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
ARE WEAKENED.
CAN YOU COMPENSATE
FOR THE LOSS?
AYE, IF WE
DON'T LOSE ANY MORE.
DON'T ASK ME
HOW IT HAPPENED.
I AM ASKING HOW, MISTER.
I WANT ANSWERS.
KIRK OUT.
WHAT'S THAT?
A STIMULANT.
BONES, HOW BAD IS IT?
2/3 OF THE PERSONNEL
ARE AFFECTED.
WHY? HOW?
DO YOU HAVE
ANY ANSWERS?
YOU KNOW YOU'LL GET
EVERYTHING I CAN TELL YOU.
BUT WHEN THERE IS NOTHING,
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO SAY?
NURSE.
THIS SHIP
IS IN TROUBLE.
WE'D BETTER START
SOLVING PROBLEMS
FASTER
THAN WE PICK UP
NEW ONES.
WE SEEM TO BE
IN THE MIDDLE OF A
CREEPING PARALYSIS.
MR. SPOCK, ANALYSIS
OF THAT LAST BURST
OF NOISE
BEFORE WE STARTED
LOSING POWER.
THAT SOUND
WAS THE TURBULENCE
CAUSED BY THE PENETRATION
OF A BOUNDARY LAYER,
CAPTAIN.
WHAT BOUNDARY LAYER?
UNKNOWN.
BOUNDARY LAYER
BETWEEN WHAT AND WHAT?
BETWEEN WHERE WE WERE
AND WHERE WE ARE.
ARE YOU TRYING TO
BE FUNNY, MR. SPOCK?
IT WOULD NEVER OCCUR
TO ME, CAPTAIN.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY IDEAS, SPOCK?
WE STILL HAVE NO SPECIFICS,
BUT WE SEEM TO HAVE ENTERED
A ZONE OF ENERGY
WHICH IS INCOMPATIBLE
WITH OUR LIVING
AND MECHANICAL PROCESSES.
AS WE DRAW CLOSER
TO THE SOURCE,
IT GROWS STRONGER
AND WE GROW WEAKER.
RECOMMENDATIONS.
I HAVE ONE.
I RECOMMEND SURVIVAL.
LET'S GET OUT
OF HERE.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WE'RE ON
A DIFFICULT MISSION,
BUT IT'S NOT THE FIRST TIME.
OUR ORDERS DO NOT SAY
"STAY ALIVE" OR "RETREAT."
OUR MISSION
IS TO INVESTIGATE.
WE'RE SICK,
AND WE'RE GETTING SICKER.
WE HAVE NO GUARANTEES,
BUT WE HAVE A GOOD SHIP
AND THE BEST CREW
IN THE STARFLEET,
SO DO YOUR JOBS.
CARRY ON.
KIRK OUT.
SICK BAY
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
GO AHEAD, BONES.
JIM, ACCORDING
TO THE LIFE INDICATORS,
THE ENERGY LEVELS...
YES, SAY IT, BONES.
ACCORDING TO
THE LIFE MONITORS,
WE'RE DYING.
WE'RE ALL DYING.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4308.8.
IT IS NOW 10 MINUTES
SINCE WE ENTERED
THE ZONE OF DARKNESS.
WE HAVE STOPPED ENGINES
WHILE WE SEEK A DEFENSE
AGAINST THE ENERGY DRAIN
WHICH SEEMS
TO PERVADE THE ZONE.
[CRASH]
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT WAS THAT?
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I'M NOT SURE.
I WAS TRYING
TO RECALIBRATE,
AND WE WENT
INTO REVERSE.
REVERSE?
THAT WAS A FORWARD LURCH.
HOW COULD THAT HAPPEN
IN REVERSE THRUST?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
ALL I KNOW IS THAT...
THE POWER LEVELS
ARE DOWN 12%
AND STEADILY DECREASING.
I'VE NEVER EXPERIENCED
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
SIR,
WE ARE ACCELERATING.
WE ARE BEING PULLED
TOWARD THE CENTER OF
THE ZONE OF DARKNESS.
BY WHAT, SPOCK?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
I SUGGEST YOU ORDER
MR. SCOTT
TO GIVE US
REVERSE POWER.
HE JUST GAVE US
WE LURCHED FORWARD.
IN THAT CASE, CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SUGGEST
WE APPLY FORWARD THRUST.
DOCTOR.
LIFE FUNCTION
INDICATORS.
THEY'VE STARTED
TO DROP AGAIN.
STIMULANTS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG
WE CAN KEEP THIS UP.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
SCOTTY?
FORWARD THRUST?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
IT GOES AGAINST
THE RULES OF LOGIC.
YES, IT DOES,
DOESN'T IT?
IF IT DOESN'T WORK,
I'LL NEVER LET SPOCK
LIVE IT DOWN.
NUDGE IT FORWARD.
BUT...
GO AHEAD.
THAT'S DOING IT, SIR.
WE'RE SLOWING DOWN.
BUT WE'RE NOT STOPPING.
WE'RE STILL BEING
DRAGGED FORWARD.
HAVE ONE OF YOUR
ENGINEERS MONITOR
THE INSTRUMENTS.
KEEP APPLYING THRUST
AGAINST THE PULL.
DOCTOR, THEY SEEM
TO BE STABILIZING.
BUT AT A DANGEROUSLY
LOW LEVEL.
WELL,
WE'RE STILL ALIVE.
I SUPPOSE
THAT'S SOMETHING.
ALL I CAN ATTRIBUTE IS,
THE FURTHER WE TRAVEL
INTO THIS ZONE OF DARKNESS,
THE WEAKER OUR
LIFE FUNCTIONS BECOME,
AND I HAVE NO IDEA WHY.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
IT'S THOSE STIMULANTS.
THEY CATCH UP WITH YOU.
ENGINEERING.
AS FAR AS THE POWER LEVELS
ARE CONCERNED, EVERYTHING
IS ACTING BACKWARDS,
BUT THE DRAIN IS CONTINUING.
ON THE STATIC TESTS,
I COULD ONLY GET 60% POWER.
WE'RE STILL BEING
DRAGGED FORWARD.
SPOCK.
IT'S LOGICAL TO ASSUME
THAT SOMETHING
WITHIN THIS ZONE
ABSORBS ALL FORMS
OF ENERGY
WHETHER MECHANICALLY OR
BIOLOGICALLY PRODUCED.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT WOULD SEEM TO BE
THE SAME THING
WHICH DREW ALL
THE ENERGY OUT OF
AN ENTIRE SOLAR SYSTEM
AND THE INTREPID.
THE SAME THING,
NOT THE ZONE ITSELF?
I WOULD SAY NOT,
CAPTAIN.
THE ANALYSIS OF THE ZONE
INDICATES IT IS
A NEGATIVE ENERGY FIELD,
HOWEVER ILLOGICAL
THAT MAY SOUND,
BUT IT IS NOT THE SOURCE
OF THE POWER DRAIN.
MAYBE IT'S A SHIELD
OF SOME KIND,
SOME FORM OF PROTECTION
FOR SOMETHING ELSE.
BUT WHAT?
WE'LL FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS,
BUT WE BETTER GET OUT
OF HERE OURSELVES.
SCOTTY, CHANNEL
ALL THE IMPULSE
AND WARP POWER
INTO ONE MASSIVE
THRUST FORWARD.
THAT MIGHT SNAP US
OUT OF THE ZONE.
AYE, CAPTAIN, BUT I'LL RESERVE
SOME FOR THE SHIELDS,
JUST IN CASE
WE DON'T GET OUT.
I SUBMIT, MR. SCOTT,
THAT IF WE DO NOT
GET OUT,
THE SHIELDS
WOULD BE EXTRANEOUS.
IT WOULD ONLY PROLONG
OUR WAIT FOR DEATH
BY A SHORT PERIOD
OF TIME.
USE WHATEVER POWER
IS NECESSARY TO GET US
OUT OF HERE, SCOTTY.
REPORT TO YOUR STATIONS,
CONTINUE YOUR RESEARCH.
DISMISSED.
CAPTAIN, THE INTREPID
WOULD'VE DONE ALL
THESE THINGS, TOO,
AND YET,
THEY WERE DESTROYED.
WELL, THEY MAY NOT
HAVE DONE ALL THESE THINGS.
YOU'VE JUST POINTED OUT
HOW ILLOGICAL
THIS SITUATION IS.
TRUE.
IT IS ALSO TRUE
THEY NEVER KNEW
WHAT WAS KILLING THEM.
THEIR LOGIC WOULD NOT
HAVE PERMITTED THEM
TO BELIEVE
THEY WERE BEING KILLED.
EXPLAIN.
VULCAN HAS NOT
BEEN CONQUERED
WITHIN ITS
COLLECTIVE MEMORY.
THE MEMORY GOES BACK
SO FAR
THAT NO VULCAN
CAN CONCEIVE
OF A CONQUEROR.
I KNEW THE SHIP WAS LOST
BECAUSE I SENSED IT.
WHAT WAS IT YOU SENSED?
A TOUCH OF DEATH.
AND WHAT DO YOU THINK
THEY FELT?
ASTONISHMENT.
AYE, THAT OUGHT TO DO IT.
ENGINEERING
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT, SCOTTY?
READY TO TRY IT WHEN
YOU ARE, SIR.
DO WE HAVE THE POWER
TO PULL IT OFF, SCOTTY?
I HOPE SO, CAPTAIN.
STAND BY.
ALL HANDS,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WE ARE SLOWLY
BEING PULLED DEEPER
INTO THE ZONE OF DARKNESS
BY AN UNKNOWN FORCE.
WE'RE GOING TO APPLY
ALL AVAILABLE POWER
INTO ONE GIANT
FORWARD THRUST
IN THE HOPE THAT IT WILL
YANK US OUT OF THE ZONE.
PREPARE YOURSELVES.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
LET'S GET ON WITH IT.
SCOTTY!
IT'S NO GOOD, SIR.
THE BEST WE CAN DO
IS TO MAINTAIN THRUST
AGAINST THE PULL
AND HOLD OUR POSITION.
ARE WE STILL
LOSING POWER?
AYE, SIR.
HOW LONG WILL
THE POWER HOLD OUT?
AT THIS RATE,
PLUS THE DRAIN
ON ALL SYSTEMS,
TWO HOURS, SIR.
MAINTAIN THRUST, SCOTTY.
WHILE WE'RE MAINTAINING
OUR DISTANCE, MR. SPOCK,
HAVE YOU ASCERTAINED YET
WHAT WE'RE MAINTAINING
OUR DISTANCE FROM?
I CANNOT SAY WHAT IT IS,
CAPTAIN,
BUT I WOULD SAY
IT HAS FOUND US.
PREPARE TO LAUNCH
A PROBE, MR. CHEKOV.
AYE, SIR.
PROBE READY FOR LAUNCH,
SIR.
GETTING VERY CONFUSED
READINGS, CAPTAIN,
BUT THIS IS
DEFINITELY THE SOURCE
OF THE ENERGY DRAIN.
LAUNCH PROBE.
PROBE LAUNCHED, SIR.
PROBE WILL IMPACT
IN 7.3 SECONDS.
6...
5...
4...3...
2...1...
[EXPLOSION]
ARE WE STILL IN CONTACT
WITH THE PROBE?
YES, SIR.
DATA BEING RELAYED
TO MR. SPOCK.
READINGS COMING IN NOW,
CAPTAIN.
LENGTH--
APPROXIMATELY 11,000 MILES.
WIDTH--VARYING
FROM 2,000 TO 3,000 MILES.
OUTER LAYER STUDDED
WITH SPACE DEBRIS
AND WASTE.
INTERIOR CONSISTS OF...
PROTOPLASM,
VARYING FROM A FIRMER
GELATINOUS LAYER
TO A SEMIFLUID
CENTRAL MASS.
CONDITION...
LIVING.
MAGNIFICATION 4.
MAGNIFICATION 4, SIR.
THAT IS WHAT IS DRAWING US
TOWARD IT, CAPTAIN,
THE SAME WAY IT DREW THE
INTREPID TO HER DEATH.
THAT IS
AN AMOEBA.
YES, I REMEMBER
MY BASIC BIOLOGY, DOCTOR.
YOU MEAN TO TELL ME
THAT THAT THING OUT THERE
IS A GIANT
SINGLE-CELLED ANIMAL?
YES, FOR LACK
OF A BETTER TERM.
IT'S A VERY SIMPLE
FORM OF LIFE.
IN FACT,
IT'S A MUCH SIMPLER
FORM OF LIFE
THAN WHAT YOU'RE
LOOKING AT NOW.
THAT THING OUT THERE
APPARENTLY CAN PERFORM
ALL THE FUNCTIONS
THAT QUALIFY IT AS
A LIVING ORGANISM.
IT CAN REPRODUCE,
IT CAN BREATHE,
IT CAN EAT,
ALTHOUGH
I DON'T KNOW WHAT.
ENERGY ITSELF, PERHAPS,
DRAINED FROM US.
I WOULD SPECULATE THAT
THIS UNKNOWN LIFE FORM
IS INVADING OUR GALAXY
LIKE A VIRUS.
THE INTREPID DIED
OF THAT PARTICULAR VIRUS.
HOW IS IT WE SURVIVE?
THE INTREPID MUST HAVE
COME ACROSS THE ORGANISM
WHILE IT WAS
STILL LOW IN ENERGY,
STILL HUNGRY.
WE ARE NOT SAFE,
CAPTAIN.
WE MERELY HAVE
A LITTLE MORE TIME
THAN THE INTREPID DID.
WHAT ABOUT THIS
ZONE OF DARKNESS?
DOES THE ORGANISM
GENERATE IT ITSELF
AS A FORM
OF PROTECTION?
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
WE'VE GOT TO FIND OUT.
GOT TO TAKE A CLOSER
LOOK AT IT.
THE CLOSER WE GET,
THE FASTER OUR
ENERGY DRAINS OUT.
WE'RE BARELY SURVIVING
AT THIS DISTANCE.
PERHAPS WE COULD
RISK THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
PERHAPS WITH
A PROTECTIVE SHIELD--
I'M NOT SENDING
ANYONE ANYWHERE.
UNMANNED PROBES CAN GIVE US
THE INFORMATION WE NEED
TO DESTROY THIS THING,
IF IT CAN BE DESTROYED.
I MUST DIFFER WITH YOU,
CAPTAIN.
WE HAVE SENT UNMANNED
PROBES INTO IT.
THEY'VE GIVEN US
SOME INFORMATION
BUT THEY'VE NOT TOLD US
WHAT WE NEED TO KNOW.
WE CANNOT AFFORD THE POWER
TO TAKE BLIND SHOTS AT IT,
HOPING TO KILL IT.
WE COULD SEND
ONE MAN IN, PINPOINT
ITS VULNERABLE SPOTS.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE ODDS
ARE IN COMING BACK?
I CAN'T ORDER
A MAN TO DO THAT.
WHO SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT AN ORDER, JIM?
YOU'VE
GOT A VOLUNTEER.
I'VE ALREADY
DONE THE
PRELIMINARY WORK.
IT'S A SUICIDE MISSION.
THE THING EVIDENTLY
HAS REFLEXES.
THE UNMANNED PROBE
WE SENT INTO IT
MUST HAVE STUNG
IT WHEN IT ENTERED.
THE LURCH WE FELT
WAS THE TURBULENCE
OF ITS REACTION.
ALL RIGHT,
SO I'D KNOW
ENOUGH TO GO SLOW
WHEN WE
PENETRATED ITS
VULNERABLE SPOTS.
YOU HAVE A MARTYR
COMPLEX, DOCTOR.
I SUBMIT THAT IT
DISQUALIFIES YOU.
DO YOU THINK
THAT I INTEND TO PASS UP
THE GREATEST LIVING
LABORATORY SINCE--
THE VULCANS
SAW IT FIRST AND DIED.
JUST BECAUSE
THE VULCANS FAILED--
I AM MORE CAPABLE.
GENTLEMEN, I AM NOT
TAKING VOLUNTEERS.
YOU DON'T THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
I'M BETTER QUALIFIED
AS A COMMAND PILOT
THAN YOU ARE.
WHICH MAKES YOU
INDISPENSABLE, CAPTAIN.
FURTHER, YOU ARE NOT
A SCIENCE SPECIALIST.
JIM, THAT ORGANISM
CONTAINS CHEMICAL
PROCESSES
WE'VE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE AND
MAY NEVER SEE AGAIN.
WE COULD LEARN MORE
IN ONE DAY--
WE DON'T HAVE
ONE DAY, DOCTOR.
WE HAVE PRECISELY
1 HOUR AND 35 MINUTES
OF POWER LEFT.
JIM--
CAPTAIN, I--
GENTLEMEN,
I'LL DECIDE.
CAPTAIN'S PERSONAL LOG--
STARDATE 4309.2.
WE HAVE ESTABLISHED
THAT THE THING
WHICH DESTROYED
THE U.S.S. INTREPID
AND THE GAMMA 7A SYSTEM
IS AN INCREDIBLY HUGE
BUT SIMPLE CELLULAR BEING
WHOSE ENERGIES ARE
TOTALLY DESTRUCTIVE
TO ALL KNOWN LIFE.
BOTH MR. SPOCK
AND DR. McCOY
HAVE VOLUNTEERED TO GO
IN A SPECIALLY EQUIPPED
SHUTTLECRAFT
TO PENETRATE THE CELL,
FIND A WAY TO DESTROY IT,
AND FREE THE SHIP.
DR. McCOY HAS THE
MEDICAL-BIOLOGICAL KNOWLEDGE.
MR. SPOCK...
IS BETTER SUITED
PHYSICALLY AND EMOTIONALLY
TO STAND THE STRESS.
BOTH ARE RIGHT,
BOTH ARE CAPABLE...
AND WHICH OF MY FRIENDS
DO I CONDEMN TO DEATH?
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK, DR. McCOY,
REPORT TO MY QUARTERS
IMMEDIATELY.
KIRK OUT.
ENGINEERING
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
YOU ASKED ME
TO KEEP YOU INFORMED
ON THE POWER DRAIN, SIR.
ALL LEVELS
ARE DOWN 50% NOW
AND STILL DRAINING.
WE CAN MAINTAIN
THRUST FOR ANOTHER
HOUR AND 15 MINUTES.
VERY WELL.
PREPARE THE SHUTTLECRAFT
FOR LAUNCHING.
SIR?
DR. McCOY WILL
TELL YOU WHAT SPECIAL
EQUIPMENT TO PUT IN IT.
KIRK OUT.
I'M SORRY,
MR. SPOCK.
RIGHT. I'LL
GET A FEW THINGS
I NEED, JIM.
NOT YOU, BONES.
I'M SORRY,
MR. SPOCK.
YOU'RE BEST
QUALIFIED TO GO.
DO NOT SUFFER SO,
DOCTOR.
THIS IS NOT THE FIRST
TIME SUPERIOR CAPABILITY
HAS PROVEN MORE VALUABLE
THAN PROFESSIONAL
CREDENTIALS.
NOTHING HAS BEEN
PROVEN YET, SPOCK.
THE DNA CODE ANALYZER
WILL GIVE YOU THE
FUNDAMENTAL STRUCTURE
OF THE THING.
YOU'LL NEED READINGS ON
THREE LIGHT WAVELENGTHS
FROM THE ENZYME RECORDER.
I AM FAMILIAR WITH
THE EQUIPMENT, DOCTOR.
WE'RE WASTING TIME.
THE SHUTTLECRAFT
IS READY.
YOU'RE DETERMINED NOT
TO LET ME SHARE IN THIS,
AREN'T YOU?
THIS IS NOT
A COMPETITION, DOCTOR.
WHETHER YOU
UNDERSTAND IT OR NOT,
GRANT ME MY
OWN KIND OF DIGNITY.
VULCAN DIGNITY?
HOW CAN I GRANT YOU
WHAT I DON'T UNDERSTAND?
THEN EMPLOY ONE OF
YOUR OWN SUPERSTITIONS.
WISH ME LUCK.
GOOD LUCK, SPOCK.
ALL SYSTEMS CLEAR FOR
SHUTTLECRAFT LAUNCH,
SIR.
LAUNCH SHUTTLECRAFT.
SHUTTLECRAFT
AWAY, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CHANNEL AUTOMATIC TELEMETRY
DIRECTLY TO THE COMPUTERS.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
[STATIC]
SHUTTLECRAFT
TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN, SPOCK.
POWER DRAIN IS ENORMOUS
AND GROWING WORSE.
CHEKOV.
DIVERTING ALL SECONDARY
POWER TO THE SHIELDS...
[STATIC]
...CONTINUE
COMMUNICATIONS
AS LONG AS THERE'S
POWER TO TRANSMIT.
HE WON'T HAVE
ENOUGH POWER
TO GET BACK OUT
IF HE DIVERTS IT
TO HIS SHIELDS.
SPOCK--
I HEARD, CAPTAIN.
WE DISCUSSED THAT
POSSIBILITY EARLIER.
BUT YOU WILL NEED
THIS INFORMATION.
WHEN DO YOU
ESTIMATE PENETRATION?
SLOWING NOW.
CONTACT IN 18.3 SECONDS.
BRACE YOURSELVES.
THE AREA
OF PENETRATION WILL
NO DOUBT BE SENSITIVE.
CONTACT...
IN SIX SECONDS.
REPORT, MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK, REPORT.
[STATIC]
I AM UNDAMAGED,
CAPTAIN.
RELAY TO
MR. SCOTT
I HAD
3% POWER RESERVE
BEFORE THE SHIELDS
STABILIZED.
THERE WAS
NOTHING TO SPARE.
I SHALL
CONTINUE MY TESTS.
OH, AND,
DR. McCOY...
YOU WOULD NOT HAVE
SURVIVED IT.
YOU WANT TO BET?
I AM MOVING SLOWLY NOW,
ESTABLISHING COURSE
TOWARD WHAT APPEARS TO
BE THE NUCLEUS.
SIR, MR. SPOCK HAS REDUCED
LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS
TO BARE MINIMUM.
SPOCK...
SAVE YOUR POWER
FOR THE SHIELDS.
CALCULATIONS INDICATE
THE SHIELDS WILL LAST
ONLY 47 MINUTES.
HOWEVER, I AM ABLE TO
IDENTIFY THE CHROMOSOME
STRUCTURE.
CHANGES INDICATE
THE ORGANISM
HAS STORED
SUFFICIENT ENERGY
FOR REPRODUCTIVE
PROCESS TO COMMENCE.
WILL THERE BE
TWO OF THOSE THINGS?
[STATIC]
I'M HAVING DIFFICULTY
MAINTAINING
SHIP CONTROL...
[STATIC]
SPOCK,
DO YOU READ ME?
[STATIC]
I'M LOSING
VOICE CONTACT--
[STATIC]
I WILL TRANSMIT
INTERNAL COORDINATES
OF CHROMOSOME BODIES.
[STATIC]
SPOCK, COME IN.
COME IN.
CONTACT LOST, SIR.
HE'S ALIVE!
HE'S KICKED IT IN
THE SIDE TO LET US KNOW.
CAPTAIN, I'M
GETTING TELEMETRY.
MR. CHEKOV, TELEMETRY
ANALYSIS AS IT COMES IN.
ACCORDING TO SPOCK'S
TELEMETRY INFORMATION,
THERE ARE
OVER 40 CHROMOSOMES
IN THE NUCLEUS
THAT ARE READY
TO COME TOGETHER,
READY TO REPRODUCE.
IF THE ENERGY OF THAT
ORGANISM ONLY DOUBLES,
WE'RE DEAD,
AND EVERYTHING WITHIN
A LIGHT YEAR WILL BE
DEFENSELESS.
WELL,
ALL I KNOW IS,
THAT SOON THERE'LL BE
TWO, FOUR, EIGHT, AND MORE.
THE ENTIRE ANTILIFE MATTER
THAT THAT THING PUTS OUT
COULD SOMEDAY ENCOMPASS
THE ENTIRE GALAXY.
SPOCK UNDERSTOOD
WHEN HE TRANSMITTED
THE COORDINATES
OF THE CHROMOSOMES.
WE MUST DESTROY
THAT ORGANISM.
CAPTAIN, THE PULL
FROM THAT ORGANISM
IS INCREASING,
AND THE POWER DRAIN
FROM OUR SHIELDS
IS GETTING CRITICAL.
HOW MUCH TIME
DO WE HAVE?
NO MORE THAN
AN HOUR NOW, SIR.
PUT ALL SECONDARY
SYSTEMS ON STANDBY.
SHIELD POWER
HAS UNCONDITIONAL
PRIORITY.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I'M RECEIVING
A MESSAGE FROM MR. SPOCK
ON A LOW-ENERGY CHANNEL.
IT'S FAINT,
BUT IT IS READABLE.
PUT IT ON,
LIEUTENANT.
ON AUDIO, SIR.
THIS IS SPOCK.
I AM SLOWLY LOSING
LIFE SUPPORT
AND MINIMAL
SHIELD ENERGIES.
ACCORDING TO
MY CALCULATIONS,
[STATIC]
NERVOUS ENERGY
OF THE ORGANISM
[STATIC LOUDER]
IS MAXIMAL...
JUST WITHIN...
ITS OUTER...
PROTECTIVE...
MEMBRANE.
RELATIVELY INSENSITIVE
TO INTERIOR IRRITATION.
[STATIC]
BELIEVE SUFFICIENT
CHARGE OF--
[STATIC]
...COULD
DESTROY THE ORGANISM.
TELL DR. McCOY...
[STATIC]
HE SHOULD HAVE
WISHED ME LUCK.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 4309.4.
WE HAVE DETERMINED WE
CAN DESTROY THE CREATURE,
PROVIDED WE CAN DO IT
FROM INSIDE THE ORGANISM.
SPOCK CLEARLY KNEW
HOW TO DESTROY IT
BUT WAS UNABLE TO
TRANSMIT THAT INFORMATION.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
OH...
WHAT'S ON YOUR MIND?
SPOCK.
IS IT ME, JIM?
AM I SO SENTIMENTAL
THAT I JUST HAVE
TO KEEP BELIEVING
THAT HE'S STILL ALIVE IN
THAT MASS OF PROTOPLASM?
HE KNEW THE ODDS
WHEN HE WENT OUT THERE,
JUST AS YOU DID WHEN
YOU VOLUNTEERED TO GO.
WHAT IS THAT THING
OUT THERE, BONES?
IT'S NOT INTELLIGENT,
NOT YET.
IT'S A...
DISEASE,
LIKE A VIRUS INVADING
THE BODY OF OUR GALAXY.
YES, IT IS, ISN'T IT?
HOW MANY CELLS DOES
A HUMAN BODY HAVE?
MILLIONS.
THIS THING, THIS CELL,
THIS VIRUS--
IT'S 11,000 MILES LONG,
AND IT'S ONE CELL.
WHEN IT
GROWS INTO MILLIONS...
WE'LL BE THE VIRUS
INVADING ITS BODY.
NOW, ISN'T
THAT A THOUGHT?
HERE WE ARE, ANTIBODIES
OF OUR OWN GALAXY,
ATTACKING
AN INVADING GERM.
BE IRONIC INDEED IF THAT
WERE OUR SOLE DESTINY,
WOULDN'T IT?
ANTIBODIES.
BRIDGE!
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
SCOTTY, HOW MUCH POWER
DO WE HAVE LEFT?
WE'RE DOWN TO 43%, SIR.
WE'RE SLIPPING A BIT
AGAINST THE PULL THAT
BEASTIE'S PUTTING ON US.
WE CAN'T LAST MORE
THAN 45 MINUTES AT THIS
RATE OF DECLINE,
LESS IF I HAVE
TO APPLY MORE THRUST.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF YOU DIVERTED
ALL REMAINING POWER
TO THE SHIELDS,
EXCEPT FOR IMPULSE POWER--
KEEP THAT IN RESERVE?
CUT THE ENGINE THRUST?
WE'D BE SUCKED INTO
THAT THING
LIKE BEING CAUGHT
IN A WIND TUNNEL, SIR.
EXACTLY. PREPARE
TO DIVERT POWER
ON MY SIGNAL.
KIRK OUT.
YOU GOT
SOMETHING TO SAY?
TECHNICALLY, NO.
MEDICALLY, YES.
BETWEEN THE STIMULANTS
AND THE PRESSURE,
I'D SUGGEST YOU TRY
TO STAY OFF YOUR FEET
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
I DON'T HAVE
A FEW MINUTES, BONES.
MAYBE NONE OF US DO.
LET'S GO.
ALL HANDS,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
WE'RE GOING TO ENTER
THE BODY OF THE ORGANISM,
RATHER ABRUPTLY,
I WOULD THINK.
DAMAGE CONTROL
PARTIES STANDBY.
ALL DECKS
SECURE FOR COLLISION.
KIRK OUT.
READY, SCOTTY.
SWITCHING POWER
TO SHIELDS,
IMPULSE
IN RESERVE,
CUTTING THRUST
TO ZERO...
NOW!
IMPACT--
FIVE SECONDS!
WE'RE THROUGH,
SIR.
I BELIEVE EVERYBODY IS
AWARE OF THAT, MR. CHEKOV.
DAMAGE CONTROL PARTIES
REPORT MINIMAL DAMAGE, SIR.
REPAIRS ARE
BEING INITIATED.
VERY GOOD, LIEUTENANT.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE ONLY
26% POWER RESERVES
AFTER ENTRY.
DO WE HAVE
IMPULSE POWER, SCOTTY?
I SAVED ALL
I COULD SIR,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER WE HAVE
ENOUGH TO GET
BACK OUT AGAIN
OR TIME, EITHER.
WE ARE COMMITTED.
AYE, WE ARE,
BUT WE'RE
COMMITTED TO WHAT?
WE HAVE NO POWER
FOR THE PHASERS.
WE COULDN'T USE IT
IF WE HAD IT.
WE'D COOK OURSELVES
ALONG WITH THAT MESS OF
PROTOPLASM OUT THERE.
THAT THING WOULD
PROBABLY LIKE PHASERS.
IT EATS POWER.
WELL, THEN, WHAT THE
DEVIL--BEGGING YOUR
PARDON, SIR--
ARE WE DOING?
MR. SPOCK WAS TRYING
TO TELL US WHAT TO DO
WHEN WE LOST VOICE CONTACT.
WE CAN'T USE THE POWER
TO DESTROY IT.
ANTIPOWER.
WHAT?
THIS THING HAS
A NEGATIVE ENERGY CHARGE.
EVERYTHING SEEMS
TO WORK IN REVERSE.
WE'LL USE ANTIMATTER.
AYE, IT COULDN'T
SWALLOW THAT.
MR. CHEKOV,
PREPARE A PROBE.
SCOTTY, WE'LL NEED
A MAGNETIC BOTTLE
FOR THE CHARGE.
HOW SOON?
IT'S ON ITS WAY, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, WE'LL USE
A TIMING DETONATOR
FOR THE PROBE.
WE'LL WORK OUT A SETTING.
AYE, SIR.
HELMSMAN, WHEN DO YOU ESTIMATE
ARRIVE ON THE NUCLEUS?
SEVEN MINUTES,
SIR.
HOW CLOSE ARE YOU
GOING TO IT?
POINT-BLANK RANGE.
WE'LL IMPLANT IT
AND BACK AWAY.
WHY? THE PROBE HAS A
RANGE OF--
WITH THE EDDIES AND
CURRENTS IN THAT PROTOPLASM,
THE PROBE COULD DRIFT
THOUSANDS OF KILOMETERS.
WE MUST BE...
EXACTLY ON TARGET,
BECAUSE WE WON'T
HAVE A SECOND CHANCE.
BONES...
TIME FOR ANOTHER
STIMULANT.
HOW LONG DO YOU THINK YOU
CAN KEEP TAKING THAT STUFF?
IT'LL BLOW YOU APART.
KEEP ME TOGETHER FOR
ANOTHER SEVEN MINUTES.
THAT'S ALL I NEED.
PERSONAL LOG--
COMMANDER SPOCK,
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
I HAVE NOTED THE PASSAGE
OF THE ENTERPRISE...
ON ITS WAY TO
WHATEVER AWAITS IT.
IF THIS RECORD
SHOULD SURVIVE ME...
I WISH IT KNOWN
THAT I BEQUEATH MY HIGHEST
COMMENDATION AND TESTIMONIAL
TO THE CAPTAIN,
OFFICERS,
AND CREW
OF THE ENTERPRISE...
THE FINEST STARSHIP
IN THE FLEET.
WE HAVE ARRIVED
AT THE CHROMOSOME BODY
IN THE NUCLEUS
OF THE ORGANISM.
IF WE SHOULD
FAIL IN OUR ATTEMPT
TO DESTROY IT
OR BE UNABLE
TO FREE OURSELVES...
I WISH TO RECORD
MY RECOMMENDATIONS FOR
THE FOLLOWING PERSONNEL,
THAT THEY RECEIVE
SPECIAL CITATION--
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
LEONARD McCOY,
MONTGOMERY SCOTT,
OFFICERS CHEKOV,
KYLE, UHURA,
AND MY HIGHEST COMMENDATION
FOR COMMANDER SPOCK,
SCIENCE OFFICER,
WHO GAVE HIS LIFE
IN THE PERFORMANCE
OF HIS DUTY.
TARGET COORDINATES
PROGRAMMED, SIR.
PROBE
READY FOR LAUNCH.
MR. SCOTT, HOW MUCH
TIME DO WE HAVE LEFT
AT 100% IMPULSE POWER?
SIX, MAYBE
SEVEN MINUTES, SIR.
MR. KYLE, PROGRAM FUSE
FOR SEVEN-MINUTE DELAY.
ALL NONESSENTIAL
SYSTEMS ON STANDBY.
COMMUNICATIONS, SCANNING--
CONSERVE
EVERY BIT OF POWER.
WE MUST MAKE IT
THROUGH THE MEMBRANE
BEFORE
THAT THING EXPLODES.
MAKE IT WORK, SCOTTY.
AYE, SIR.
PROGRAMMING COMPLETE.
READY FOR LAUNCH.
LAUNCH PROBE
AT ZERO ACCELERATION.
FORWARD THRUST OFF
1/10 OF A SECOND.
FORWARD THRUST
OFF, SIR.
PROBE LAUNCHED,
SIR.
DESPITE WHAT SPOCK SAID,
IT'S STILL PLENTY SENSITIVE.
PROBE CONFIRMED.
IT IS LODGED
IN THE NUCLEUS
NEAR THE CHROMOSOME
BODIES.
MR. KYLE, BACK US OUT
THE WAY WE CAME IN.
MR. CHEKOV,
A NICE STRAIGHT LINE.
DON'T WASTE ANY TIME.
BACKING OUT,
SIR.
ESTIMATE
WE'LL BE OUT IN...
6.37 MINUTES.
VERY GOOD.
CAPTAIN,
METALLIC SUBSTANCE
OUTSIDE THE SHIP.
SPOCK!
LIEUTENANT, GET ME
SPOCK'S VOICE CHANNEL.
HIGHEST POSSIBLE GAIN.
GO AHEAD, SIR.
SPOCK, DO YOU READ ME?
DO YOU READ ME, SPOCK?
DO YOU READ ME?
COME IN, SPOCK.
SPOCK!
SCOTTY,
GET A TRACTOR BEAM.
CAPTAIN, WE DON'T
HAVE ENOUGH TIME
TO DO IT.
WE ONLY HAVE
A 53-SECOND
ESCAPE MARGIN.
I'M WELL AWARE OF THAT,
MR. SCOTT.
GET TWO TRACTOR BEAMS
ON THAT SHUTTLECRAFT.
AYE, SIR.
TRACTOR BEAMS ON.
[SPOCK]
CAPTAIN, I RECOMMEND
YOU ABANDON THE ATTEMPT.
DO NOT RISK THE SHIP
FURTHER ON MY BEHALF.
SHUT UP, SPOCK!
WE'RE RESCUING YOU.
WHY, THANK YOU,
CAPTAIN McCOY.
ALMOST OUT.
WE'RE APPROACHING
THE MEMBRANE, SIR.
TIME UNTIL EXPLOSION?
57 SECONDS, SIR.
MAINTAINING TRACTOR BEAMS
ON SHUTTLECRAFT, MR. SCOTT?
AYE, SIR.
BUT I CAN'T GUARANTEE
IT'LL HOLD WHEN
THE WARHEAD EXPLODES.
THE POWER LEVELS ARE--
THE POWER LEVELS
ARE DEAD, SIR.
YOU MAY HAVE JUST WRITTEN
OUR EPITAPH, MR. SCOTT.
[LARGE CRASH]
ACTIVATE
MAIN VIEWING SCREEN.
MR. CHEKOV, REPORT.
THE ORGANISM
IS DESTROYED, SIR.
THE EXPLOSION
MUST HAVE RUPTURED
THE MEMBRANE
AND THROWN US CLEAR.
THE POWER'S
COMING BACK, SIR.
SHUTTLECRAFT?
I DON'T KNOW HOW,
SIR, BUT IT'S
STILL WITH US.
SHUTTLECRAFT
TO ENTERPRISE.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO COME ABOARD.
SPOCK, YOU'RE ALIVE!
OBVIOUSLY, CAPTAIN.
AND I HAVE SOME
FASCINATING DATA
ON THE ORGANISM.
DON'T BE
SO SMART, SPOCK.
YOU BOTCHED
THE ACETYLCHOLINE TEST.
LATER, LATER, LATER.
HA HA HA HA.
BRING THE SHUTTLECRAFT
ABOARD, UH, MR. SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
Kyle:
PREPARE TO RECEIVE
SHUTTLECRAFT.
RECEIVED
HANGAR DOORS
CLOSED.
HANGAR DECK
PRESSURIZING.
MR. CHEKOV, LAY IN
A COURSE FOR STARBASE 6.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 5.
I'M STILL LOOKING FORWARD
TO A NICE PERIOD
OF REST AND RELAXATION
ON SOME LOVELY...
PLANET.