[BEEP BEEP]
YES, JIM.
HOW MUCH LONGER,
McCOY?
OH, ABOUT
ANOTHER 30 MINUTES.
I'VE COME ACROSS
SOME MOST INTERESTING
ORGANIC COMPOUNDS.
HEY,
STARFLEET WAS RIGHT.
THESE, UH, ROOTS
AND SOIL CULTURES
CAN BE A MEDICAL
TREASURE HOUSE.
ANY PROBLEMS THERE?
NO SIGN OF THE INHABITANTS
SO FAR. KIRK OUT.
LARGE PRINTS.
THE APELIKE CARNIVORE
IN THE REPORTS?
YES, THE MUGATO.
NO PROBLEM, THOUGH.
THOSE PRINTS ARE
SEVERAL DAYS OLD.
THEY SELDOM STAY
AROUND IN ONE PLACE.
ASIDE FROM THAT,
YOU SAY IT'S
A GARDEN OF EDEN.
OR SO IT SEEMED
TO THE BRASH YOUNG
LIEUTENANT KIRK
IN COMMAND
OF HIS FIRST
PLANET SURVEY.
CLASS "M" IN ALL RESPECTS.
QUITE EARTHLIKE.
EXCEPT THESE PEOPLE
STAYED IN THEIR
GARDEN OF EDEN.
BOWS AND ARROWS
FOR HUNTING,
BUT ABSOLUTELY
NO FIGHTING
AMONG THEMSELVES.
REMARKABLY
PEACEFUL...
AND TRANQUIL.
[MAN]
HO! TAKE COVER HERE!
BOWS AND ARROWS, CAPTAIN?
VILLAGERS
WITH FLINTLOCKS.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THEY HADN'T PROGRESSED
NEARLY THAT FAR.
CAPTAIN, LOOK.
ONE OF THOSE MEN
WALKING INTO AMBUSH
IS TYREE--
THE FRIEND
I LIVED WITH HERE.
CAPTAIN...
USE OF OUR PHASERS
IS EXPRESSLY FORBIDDEN.
VILLAGERS!
"ENTERPRISE," ALERT!
STAND BY TO BEAM UP
LANDING PARTY.
SPOCK?
YOUR PHASER!
NO, CAPTAIN.
I CAN TRAVEL.
BEAM US UP, QUICKLY.
NOW, SCOTTY.
HAVE MEDICS
STAND BY.
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
WHAT HAPPENED,
CAPTAIN?
LEAD PROJECTILE.
PRIMITIVE FIREARM.
VITALIZER "B."
PRESSURE PACKET.
WE'RE LUCKY
HIS HEART'S WHERE
HIS LIVER SHOULD BE,
OR HE'D BE DEAD NOW.
NOT GOOD, SIR.
CORANALIN!
BONES,
CAN YOU
SAVE HIM?
[ALARM BLARES]
[UHURA]
ALL DECKS, RED ALERT!
BATTLE STATIONS,
BATTLE STATIONS!
GO TO RED ALERT!
KIRK HERE.
UHURA, SIR.
WE HAVE A KLINGON VESSEL
ON OUR SCREENS.
ON MY WAY.
SCOTTY.
BONES?
I DON'T KNOW YET,
JIM.
[ALARM BLARING]
CAPTAIN, WE'RE
HOLDING THE PLANET
BETWEEN US
AND THE KLINGONS.
I DON'T THINK
THEY'VE SPOTTED US.
MAKE THAT
DEFINITE, SIR.
THEY'RE SENDING
A ROUTINE MESSAGE
TO THEIR HOMEBASE,
NO MENTION OF US.
GOOD.
GO TO YELLOW ALERT.
YELLOW ALERT.
ALL STATIONS,
GO TO YELLOW ALERT.
DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN KEEP US OUT OF
THEIR SIGHT, CHEKOV?
I CAN TRY, CAPTAIN.
MESSAGE
TO STARBASE, SIR?
NO POINT IN
GIVING OURSELVES AWAY,
LIEUTENANT,
UNTIL WE FIND OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON.
WE CAN HIDE FOR
A WHILE, SIR,
BUT WE MAY HAVE
TO GO OUT OF ORBIT
TO KEEP IT UP
FOR LONG.
KIRK TO SICKBAY.
McCOY HERE.
I'LL CALL YOU
SOON AS I KNOW ANYTHING.
SICKBAY OUT.
SO THEY'VE
BROKEN THE TREATY.
NOT NECESSARILY, CAPTAIN.
THEY HAVE AS MUCH RIGHT
TO SCIENTIFIC MISSIONS HERE
AS WE HAVE.
RESEARCH IS NOT
THE KLINGON WAY.
TRUE, BUT SINCE THIS IS
A HANDS-OFF PLANET,
HOW ARE YOU GONNA PROVE
THEY'RE DOING OTHERWISE?
WHEN I LEFT THERE
13 YEARS AGO,
THOSE VILLAGERS
HAD BARELY LEARNED
TO FORGE IRON.
SPOCK WAS SHOT
WITH A FLINTLOCK.
HOW MANY CENTURIES
BETWEEN THOSE
TWO DEVELOPMENTS?
ON EARTH,
ABOUT 12, SIR.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
A FLINTLOCK WOULD
BE THE FIRST FIREARM
THE INHABITANTS
WOULD NORMALLY
DEVELOP.
YES, I'M AWARE
OF THAT, MR. SCOTT.
AND, SIR,
THE FACT THAT EARTH
TOOK 12 CENTURIES
DOESN'T MEAN
THEY HAD TO.
WE'VE SEEN DEVELOPMENT
AT DIFFERENT RATES
ON DIFFERENT PLANETS.
AND IF THERE WERE
THE KLINGONS
BEHIND IT,
WHY DIDN'T THEY GIVE
THEM BREECHLOADERS?
OR MACHINE GUNS?
OR OLD-STYLE
HAND LASERS?
I DID NOT
INVITE A DEBATE.
I'M SORRY.
I'M WORRIED
ABOUT SPOCK
AND CONCERNED
ABOUT WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO SOMETHING
I ONCE KNEW DOWN THERE.
YOU HAVE
THE CON, SCOTTY.
I'LL BE AT SICKBAY.
WE'VE NO REPLACEMENTS
FOR THE DAMAGED ORGANS, SIR.
IF HE'S GOING TO LIVE,
HIS VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY
WILL HAVE TO DO IT
FOR HIM.
AGREED.
STERILITE OFF.
YES, SIR.
HE'LL LIVE OR DIE NOW,
JIM.
I DON'T KNOW WHICH.
DR. M'BENGA INTERNED
IN A VULCAN WARD.
HE COULDN'T BE
IN BETTER HANDS.
THEN YOU AND I ARE
TRANSPORTING DOWN,
BONES.
I CAN'T LEAVE SPOCK
AT THIS TIME.
YOU JUST INDICATED
YOU COULD.
THERE ARE
KLINGONS HERE.
IF THEIR MISSION
IS A LEGITIMATE
RESEARCH INTEREST
IN THE PLANET'S
ORGANIC POTENTIAL,
THEN YOU'RE
THE ONE MAN
WHO CAN TELL ME.
AND IF THAT'S NOT IT?
THEN I NEED HELP--
ADVICE I CAN TRUST
AS MUCH AS SPOCK'S.
I APPRECIATE
THE COMPLIMENT, JIM, BUT--
BONES, I'M AS WORRIED
ABOUT SPOCK AS YOU ARE.
IF THE KLINGONS ARE
BREAKING THE TREATY...
IT COULD BE
INTERSTELLAR WAR.
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
BRIDGE. SCOTT HERE.
McCOY AND I
ARE TRANSPORTING
BACK DOWN.
INFORM SHIP'S STORES
THAT WE'LL NEED
NATIVE COSTUMES.
CAPTAIN, WE MAY HAVE TO BREAK
OUT OF ORBIT ANY MINUTE
TO KEEP OUT OF THEIR SIGHT.
WE'D BE OUT OF
COMMUNICATOR RANGE WITH YOU.
I UNDERSTAND.
WE'LL ARRANGE
A RENDEZVOUS
SCHEDULE.
KIRK OUT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4211.4.
KEEPING OUR PRESENCE HERE
SECRET
IS AN ENORMOUS
TACTICAL ADVANTAGE,
THEREFORE I CANNOT
RISK CONTACT
WITH STARFLEET COMMAND.
I MUST TAKE ACTION
ON MY OWN JUDGMENT.
I HAVE ELECTED
TO VIOLATE ORDERS
AND MAKE CONTACT WITH
PLANET INHABITANTS HERE.
PERFECT.
TYREE'S CAMP IS
A QUARTER A MILE AWAY.
WANT TO THINK
ABOUT IT AGAIN, JIM?
STARFLEET'S ORDERS
ABOUT THIS PLANET
STATE
NO INTERFERENCE.
NO INTERFERENCE
WITH NORMAL
SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT.
I'M NOT ONLY
AWARE OF IT,
IT WAS MY SURVEY
13 YEARS AGO
THAT RECOMMENDED IT.
I READ IT.
"INHABITANTS SUPERIOR
IN MANY WAYS TO HUMANS.
"LEFT ALONE,
THEY UNDOUBTEDLY
SOMEDAY WILL DEVELOP
A REMARKABLY ADVANCED
AND PEACEFUL CULTURE."
INDEED.
AND I INTEND TO SEE
THAT THEY HAVE THAT CHANCE.
YOU COMING WITH ME?
DO I HAVE A CHOICE?
[ARRGGHH]
AAH! AAH!
ARGH! ARGH!
[ARRGGHH]
CONTACT THE SHIP.
TOOK FULL POISON.
FANGS.
OHH...
"ENTERPRISE," McCOY.
EMERGENCY. COME IN!
"ENTERPRISE," COME IN.
McCOY!
EMERGENCY!
THEY LEFT.
OUT OF ORBIT.
OOH!
JIM, THERE
IS NO ANTITOXIN
FOR THIS POISON.
I CAN ONLY
KEEP YOU ALIVE
A FEW HOURS
WITH THIS.
TYREE...
SOME OF HIS MEN.
CURE.
OH!
ARE YOU
HILL PEOPLE?
DO YOU KNOW
A HUNTER
NAMED TYREE?
A MUGATO
ATTACKED HIM.
HE'S JAMES KIRK.
HE'S A FRIEND
OF TYREE'S.
BLAST IT!
DO SOMETHING!
HE'S DYING!
TAKE HIM
TO THE CAVE.
I BRING TYREE.
[DR. McCOY]
MEDICAL LOG,
STARDATE 4211.8.
KIRK IS RIGHT
ABOUT THE PEOPLE HERE.
DESPITE THEIR FEAR
AND OUR STRANGENESS,
THEY'RE COMPASSIONATE
AND GENTLE.
I'VE LEARNED
THE HUNTER TYREE
IS NOW THEIR LEADER.
HE IS EXPECTED
TO RETURN SHORTLY
WITH HIS WIFE,
WHO THEY SAY
KNOWS HOW TO CURE
THIS POISON.
MY PROBLEM--
THE CAPTAIN
IS IN DEEP SHOCK.
I MUST KEEP HIM WARM
AND ALIVE UNTIL THEN.
YOU AND YOUR
GARDEN OF EDEN.
[WHIRRING]
WE MUST OBTAIN
THE SAME FIRESTICKS,
HUSBAND.
YOU COULD BE
KILLING THEM INSTEAD.
WE COULD TAKE
THEIR HOUSES...
THEIR GOODS.
NONA, NONA.
ENOUGH.
IN TIME
THE VILLAGERS
WILL RETURN
TO THEIR WAYS
OF FRIENDSHIP.
IN TIME?
THEY KILL
YOUR PEOPLE!
I AM A KAHN-UT-TU WOMAN.
IN ALL THIS LAND,
HOW MANY ARE THERE?
MEN SEEK US
BECAUSE THROUGH US
THEY BECOME GREAT LEADERS.
I TOOK YOU
BECAUSE YOU CAST
A SPELL UPON ME.
AND I HAVE SPELLS
THAT HELP ME KEEP YOU.
REMEMBER THIS LEAF?
THE NIGHT WE CAMPED
BY THE WATER?
MMM. THE NIGHT
OF MADNESS.
OH, TYREE,
DID YOU REALLY
HATE THAT MADNESS?
NO, NONA.
NO!
IT BROUGHT UP
EVIL BEASTS
FROM MY SOUL.
ONLY ONE
LOVELY BEAST, TYREE,
MY HUGE, ANGRY MAN.
FORGIVE ME.
WHAT IS IT?
THERE ARE STRANGERS
IN OUR CAMP.
ONE HAS TAKEN
THE MUGATO BITE.
HE DIES.
STRANGERS?
IT IS SAID
THE DYING ONE
IS A FRIEND OF TYREE
FROM LONG AGO.
THAT ONE.
BRING HIM
WHEN HIS HEAD CLEARS.
THE STRANGER,
WHERE IS HE?
NONA, WHERE IS KIRK?
THE CAVE.
TYREE.
YOU WISH ME
TO SAVE HIM?
YOU MUST.
HE IS THE ONE
I TOLD YOU OF,
THE FRIEND OF
MY YOUNGER DAYS.
MY REMEDIES REQUIRE
I KNOW WHAT KIND OF
MAN HE IS--
ALL THAT IS KNOWN
OF HIM.
I GAVE HIM
MY PROMISE OF SILENCE.
HE WAS MADE MY BROTHER.
AND I'M YOUR WIFE,
HIS SISTER.
I PROMISE SILENCE,
ALSO.
- NONA--
- QUICKLY!
OR HE DIES.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR
CLOSES]
DON'T LET THESE
LOW PANEL READINGS
BOTHER YOU.
I'VE SEEN THIS
BEFORE IN VULCANS.
IT'S THEIR WAY
OF CONCENTRATING
ALL THEIR STRENGTH,
BLOOD, AND ANTIBODIES
ONTO
THE INJURED ORGANS,
A FORM OF SELF-INDUCED
HYPNOSIS.
YOU MEAN
HE'S CONSCIOUS?
WELL, IN A SENSE.
HE KNOWS WE'RE HERE
AND WHAT WE'RE SAYING,
BUT HE CAN'T AFFORD
TO TAKE HIS MIND
FROM THE TISSUE
HE'S FIGHTING TO HEAL.
I SUPPOSE HE EVEN KNOWS
YOU WERE HOLDING HIS HAND.
A GOOD NURSE ALWAYS
TREATS HER PATIENTS
THAT WAY.
IT PROVES
SHE'S INTERESTED.
I AM TYREE.
AND I AM TYREE'S WOMAN.
IT'S KIRK.
SHE WILL
CURE HIM.
WHAT'S THAT?
A MAHKO ROOT.
A PLANT?
IT MOVES.
FOR THOSE WHO KNOW
WHERE TO FIND IT,
HOW TO USE IT,
HOW TO PICK IT.
[GROANING]
TAKE THIS
OF MY SOUL...
THIS OF MY SOUL...
INTO THINE...
[GROANS]
DEEPLY...
TOGETHER...
YOUR PAIN IS MINE...
ALL OF MINE...
FILL THIS SOUL
OF MINE.
TOGETHER!
RETURN.
IT IS PAST.
RETURN!
BONES...
I HAD
THE STRANGEST DREAM.
HOW DO
YOU FEEL, JIM?
TIRED.
VERY TIRED.
YOU DID A FINE JOB, BONES.
I THINK I'LL S...
SLEEP.
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR SAVING HIS LIFE.
I WOULD LIKE TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THIS.
OUR BLOOD HAS
PASSED THROUGH
THE MAHKO ROOT TOGETHER.
OUR SOULS
HAVE BEEN TOGETHER.
HE IS MINE NOW.
SHE MUST SLEEP, ALSO.
HE IS HERS?
WHEN A MAN AND WOMAN
ARE JOINED
IN THIS MANNER,
HE CAN REFUSE HER
NO WISH.
BUT IT IS
ONLY LEGEND.
Jim.
BONES.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
TYREE...
MY OLD FRIEND.
YES, JAMES!
JAMES, IT IS GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
WHAT
AM I DOING HERE?
MUGATO BITE.
I REMEMBER.
I TOLD HIM TO TAKE ME
TO TYREE'S CAMP.
I KNEW YOU'D FIND
A KAHN-UT-TU TO CURE ME.
A KAHN-UT-TU IS THE LOCAL
WITCH PEOPLE HERE.
THEY'VE STUDIED...
THEY HAVE STUDIED THE...
ROOTS...
AND THE HERBS.
I AM A KAHN-UT-TU,
CAPTAIN.
I CURED YOU.
MY WIFE--NONA.
YES, OF COURSE.
I SHOULD'VE GUESSED.
CONGRATULATIONS.
TYREE, WE MUST TALK, NOW.
THE VILLAGERS,
THEIR NEW WEAPONS--
I WANT TO HEAR
ALL ABOUT THAT.
WE MUST MAKE PLANS.
GOOD.
IT IS PAST TIME
TO PLAN.
MUCH HAS HAPPENED
SINCE YOU LEFT, JAMES.
COME.
WE'LL SPEAK OF IT.
AND OF THINGS
TO BE DONE.
COME.
WE WILL SPEAK
OF IT.
READINGS ARE BEGINNING
TO FLUCTUATE.
JUST AS THEY SHOULD.
THIS IS DR. M'BENGA.
THERE WILL BE
SOMEONE WITH YOU
CONSTANTLY NOW.
WHEN THE TIME COMES,
I'LL BE CALLED.
AS SOON AS
HE SHOWS ANY SIGNS
OF CONSCIOUSNESS,
CALL ME IMMEDIATELY.
YES, DOCTOR.
AFTER YOU'VE CALLED ME,
IF HE SPEAKS,
DO WHATEVER HE SAYS.
DO WHATEVER
HE SAYS?
YES.
WELL, THAT'S CLEAR
ENOUGH, ISN'T IT?
THE FIRESTICKS
FIRST APPEARED
NEARLY A YEAR AGO.
SINCE THAT TIME,
MANY OF MY PEOPLE HAVE DIED.
YOU SAY THEY MAKE
THE FIRESTICKS
THEMSELVES?
HOW CAN YOU
BE SURE?
I HAVE LOOKED
INTO THEIR VILLAGE.
I HAVE SEEN IT BEING DONE.
HAVE YOU SEEN
ANY STRANGERS
AMONG THE VILLAGERS?
STRANGERS?
NO.
CAN YOU TAKE US
TO THEIR VILLAGE
WHILE IT'S
STILL DARK?
YES, BUT THE MUGATOS
TRAVEL AT NIGHT, ALSO.
YOU KILLED ONE.
ITS MATE WILL NOT BE FAR.
HAVE YOU SEEN
HOW THESE WORK?
I'VE SEEN THEM, ALSO.
AND I KNOW
YOU HAVE MANY WAYS
TO MAKE YOUR FRIEND TYREE
A MAN OF GREAT IMPORTANCE.
MANY WAYS?
WHAT ELSE
DOES SHE KNOW ABOUT US?
TYREE HAS TOLD ME
MUCH OF YOU.
DO NOT BLAME HIM.
IT WAS THE PRICE
FOR SAVING YOUR LIFE.
WE'RE SIMPLY STRANGERS
FROM...
FROM ONE OF THE LIGHTS
IN THE SKY,
AND YOU HAVE WAYS
AS FAR ABOVE FIRESTICKS
AS THE SKY
ABOVE OUR WORLD.
YOU WILL NOT
SPEAK OF THIS
TO OTHERS.
I WILL NOT IF I AM MADE
TO UNDERSTAND.
TEACH ME.
THERE'S AN OLD CUSTOM
AMONG MY PEOPLE.
WHEN A WOMAN
SAVES A MAN'S LIFE,
HE IS GRATEFUL.
I AM GRATEFUL.
A SPLENDID CUSTOM...
IF NOT CARRIED
TO EXTREMES.
WE ONCE WERE
AS YOU ARE--
SPEARS, ARROWS.
THERE CAME A TIME
WHEN OUR WEAPONS
GREW FASTER
THAN OUR WISDOM,
AND WE ALMOST
DESTROYED OURSELVES.
WE LEARNED FROM THIS
TO MAKE A RULE
DURING ALL OUR TRAVELS--
NEVER TO CAUSE
THE SAME TO HAPPEN
TO OTHER WORLDS,
JUST AS A MAN MUST GROW
IN HIS OWN WAY
AND IN HIS OWN TIME.
SOME MEN NEVER GROW.
PERHAPS NOT AS FAST
OR IN THE WAY ANOTHER
THINKS HE SHOULD.
BUT WE'RE WISE ENOUGH
TO KNOW
THAT WE ARE WISE ENOUGH
NOT TO INTERFERE
IN THE WAY OF A MAN
OR ANOTHER WORLD.
YOU MUST LET THE VILLAGERS
DESTROY US?
YOU WILL NOT HELP
YOUR FRIEND AND BROTHER
KILL THEM INSTEAD?
NO!
I SAID
I WILL NOT KILL!
WE MUST FIGHT OR DIE!
IS DYING BETTER?
YOU WOULD LET HIM DIE
WHEN YOU HAVE WEAPONS
TO MAKE HIM POWERFUL
AND SAFE?
THEN HE HAS
THE WRONG FRIENDS.
AND I HAVE
THE WRONG HUSBAND...
YOU WILL HELP IN WAYS
SHE DOES NOT UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE FAITH
IN OUR FRIENDSHIP, JAMES.
COME, BEFORE WE
LOSE THE DARKNESS.
WHAT'S BOTHERING
YOU, JIM?
IF WE FIND THE KLINGONS
HAVE HELPED THE VILLAGERS,
THERE'S CERTAINLY
SOMETHING WE CAN DO.
THAT'S
WHAT'S BOTHERING ME--
THERE'S SOMETHING
WE MAY HAVE TO DO.
GUARD. WE MUST WAIT.
TYREE, SUPPOSING
YOU HAD TO FIGHT.
WHAT THEN?
JIM,
THIS MAN BELIEVES
IN THE SAME THING
WE BELIEVE IN,
THAT KILLING IS STUPID
AND USELESS.
TYREE?
NOW. COME.
GUN, AMMUNITION.
DOCTOR.
YOU ARE LATE,
MY FRIEND APELLA.
A QUARREL BY MY PEOPLE,
THE DIVISION
OF SOME SKINS
AND A HILL WOMAN
TAKEN THIS MORNING.
IT'S HARD TO DIVIDE
ONE WOMAN.
GIVE HER TO THE MAN
WHO KILLED THE MOST
OF HER PEOPLE.
THE OTHERS WILL SEE
THE PROFIT IN BRAVERY.
I'LL MAKE A KLINGON
OF YOU YET.
NOW, YOUR NEXT
IMPROVEMENT...
NOTICE WHAT WE'VE DONE
TO THE STRIKER.
SEE HOW IT HOLDS
THE PRIMING POWDER
MORE SECURELY?
FEWER MISFIRES.
WHEN I RETURN,
WE WILL GIVE YOU
OTHER IMPROVEMENTS.
RIFLED BARREL--
WHAT?
A WAY TO SHOOT
FURTHER AND STRAIGHTER.
JIM.
COAL FOR A FORGE.
SULFUR FOR GUNPOWDER.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK
INSIDE.
WELL, HERE'S
YOUR FORGE.
[TRICORDER BEEPING]
PEOPLE'S EXHIBIT
NUMBER ONE--
CHROME STEEL DRILL POINT.
THIS PIG IRON
IS ALMOST CARBON-FREE.
THAT VILLAGE FURNACE
CERTAINLY DIDN'T
PRODUCE IT.
PEOPLE'S EXHIBIT
NUMBER TWO--
COLD-ROLLED
GUN BARREL ROD
FASHIONED
TO LOOK HOMEMADE.
YOU WERE RIGHT ABOUT
THE KLINGONS, JIM.
MAKE RECORDER
AND SCANNER TAPES
OF EVERYTHING.
RIGHT.
IT'S A PITY WE CAN'T
INCLUDE A LIVE KLINGON--
THAT'D JUST ABOUT WRAP--
[APELLA]
IS IT DIFFICULT TO CUT SMALL
GROOVES INTO THE BARRELS?
[KRELL]
IT'S QUITE SIMPLE.
I'LL SHOW YOU
THE METHOD.
I THOUGHT MY PEOPLE
WOULD GROW TIRED
OF KILLING,
BUT YOU WERE RIGHT.
THEY SEE THAT
IT IS EASIER
THAN TRADING
AND IT HAS
PLEASURES.
I FEEL IT MYSELF,
LIKE THE HUNT,
BUT WITH
RICHER REWARDS.
YOU WILL BE RICH
ONE DAY, APELLA,
BEYOND YOUR DREAMS,
THE LEADER
OF A WHOLE WORLD,
A GOVERNOR...
IN THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
[BEEPING]
BONES!
GUARDS!
INTRUDERS!
MOVE! FAST!
[GUNSHOT]
NURSE.
YES?
HIT ME. THE PAIN WILL
HELP ME TO
CONSCIOUSNESS. HIT ME.
HIT YOU? NO! I CAN'T--
I ASK YOU,
STRIKE ME.
IF I DON'T REGAIN
CONSCIOUSNESS SOON,
IT MAY BE TOO LATE.
HIT ME!
HARDER!
AGAIN!
CONTINUE.
THE PAIN WILL HELP ME
TO CONSCIOUSNESS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
WOMAN?
LEAVE ME ALONE!
HAVE YOU GONE DAFT?
MR. SPOCK NEEDS ME!
LET GO!
THAT WILL BE
QUITE ENOUGH.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
PLEASE...
RELEASE HER.
WHAT'S THIS
ALL ABOUT?
SHE WAS DOING
AS I REQUESTED,
MR. SCOTT,
A VULCAN FORM
OF SELF-HEALING.
AS YOU SAW,
THEY MUST WAIT UNTIL
THE LAST POSSIBLE MOMENT,
THEN FIGHT THEIR WAY
BACK TO CONSCIOUSNESS.
HERE, LET ME HELP YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
THANK YOU, NURSE.
I'M QUITE
FULLY RECOVERED.
YES, I SEE YOU ARE.
MEN, THIS IS THE PAN.
THIS IS THE HAMMER.
THE HAMMER
STRIKING THE PAN
CAUSES A SPARK,
IGNITES THE POWDER,
AND FIRES
THE FLINTLOCK.
NOW AIM IT
AS I SHOWED YOU.
HOLD YOUR BREATH
AND SQUEEZE THE TRIGGER
GENTLY.
WELL DONE.
VERY, VERY,
VERY GOOD.
JIM, I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
NOT HERE, BONES.
IN THE CAVE.
YUTAN, YOUR TURN.
DO I HAVE TO SAY IT?
IT'S NOT BAD ENOUGH
THERE'S ALREADY ONE
SERPENT IN EDEN
TEACHING ONE SIDE
ABOUT GUNPOWDER,
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
SURE THEY ALL
KNOW ABOUT IT!
EXACTLY.
EACH SIDE RECEIVES
THE SAME KNOWLEDGE
AND THE SAME TYPE
OF FIREARM.
HAVE YOU GONE
OUT OF YOUR MIND?
YES, MAYBE YOU HAVE.
TYREE'S WIFE--
SHE SAID
THERE WAS SOMETHING
IN THAT ROOT.
SHE SAID NOW
THAT YOU CAN
REFUSE HER NOTHING.
SUPERSTITION.
IS IT A COINCIDENCE
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHAT SHE WANTS?
IS IT? SHE WANTS
SUPERIOR WEAPONS.
THAT'S THE ONE THING
NEITHER SIDE CAN HAVE.
BONES...
BONES, THE NORMAL
DEVELOPMENT OF THIS PLANET
WAS THE STATUS QUO
BETWEEN THE HILL PEOPLE
AND THE VILLAGERS.
THE KLINGONS CHANGED THAT
WITH THE FLINTLOCKS.
IF THIS PLANET
IS TO DEVELOP
THE WAY IT SHOULD,
WE MUST EQUALIZE
BOTH SIDES AGAIN.
JIM, THAT MEANS
YOU'RE CONDEMNING
THIS WHOLE PLANET
TO A WAR
THAT MAY NEVER END.
IT COULD GO ON
FOR YEAR AFTER YEAR,
MASSACRE
AFTER MASSACRE.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR!
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
SAY I'M WRONG.
SAY I'M DRUGGED.
SAY THE WOMAN DRUGGED ME.
WHAT IS YOUR SOBER,
SENSIBLE SOLUTION
TO ALL THIS?
I DON'T HAVE
A SOLUTION.
BUT FURNISHING THEM
FIREARMS
IS CERTAINLY
NOT THE ANSWER.
BONES, DO YOU REMEMBER
THE 20th-CENTURY
BRUSH WARS
ON THE ASIAN CONTINENT?
TWO GIANT POWERS INVOLVED,
MUCH LIKE THE KLINGONS
AND OURSELVES.
NEITHER SIDE FELT
THAT THEY COULD PULL OUT.
YES, I REMEMBER.
IT WENT ON
BLOODY YEAR AFTER
BLOODY YEAR.
WELL, WHAT WOULD YOU
HAVE SUGGESTED,
THAT ONE SIDE ARM ITS FRIENDS
WITH AN OVERPOWERING WEAPON?
MANKIND WOULD NEVER HAVE LIVED
TO TRAVEL SPACE IF THEY HAD.
NO. THE ONLY SOLUTION
IS WHAT HAPPENED BACK THEN.
BALANCE OF POWER.
AND IF THE KLINGONS
GIVE THEIR SIDE
EVEN MORE?
THEN WE ARM OUR SIDE
WITH EXACTLY THAT MUCH MORE.
A BALANCE OF POWER--
THE TRICKIEST,
MOST DIFFICULT,
DIRTIEST GAME
OF THEM ALL,
BUT THE ONLY ONE
THAT PRESERVES BOTH SIDES.
AND WHAT ABOUT
YOUR FRIEND TYREE?
WILL HE UNDERSTAND
THIS BALANCE OF POWER?
NO.
PROBABLY NOT,
BUT I'M GOING TO HAVE TO TRY
AND MAKE HIM UNDERSTAND.
I NEVER HAD A MORE
DIFFICULT TASK.
WELL, JIM,
HERE'S ANOTHER MORSEL
OF AGONY FOR YOU.
SINCE TYREE WON'T FIGHT,
HE WILL BE
ONE OF THE FIRST TO DIE.
WELL...
WAR ISN'T A GOOD LIFE,
BUT IT'S...LIFE.
HIS WIFE IS THE ONLY WAY
TO REACH HIM.
IF I TELL HER
WE'RE GOING
TO SUPPLY GUNS...
MAYBE...
SHE'LL CONVINCE HIM.
POSITION,
MR. SCOTT?
ENTERING
DISTANT ORBIT, SIR.
APPROACHING
RENDEZVOUS TIME.
THE KLINGONS?
THEY HAVEN'T
SPOTTED US YET, SIR.
LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE
BEAMING SOMEONE
ABOARD.
STAND BY
TO SIGNAL THE CAPTAIN.
AYE, SIR.
NONA. PARDON ME.
YOU ARE HERE BECAUSE
I WISHED YOU HERE.
OH? I THOUGHT
IT WAS MY IDEA.
YES. THEY ALWAYS BELIEVE
THEY COME OF FREE WILL.
TYREE EVEN
THOUGHT THE SAME
WHEN I CAST
MY FIRST SPELL ON HIM.
NONA--
CAN YOU SMELL
THIS FRAGRANCE?
SOME FIND IT
PLEASING.
I WOULD LIKE
TO TALK TO YOU.
AGAIN.
SOME FIND IT
SOOTHING.
YES.
I WOULD LIKE...
HAPPY.
YES. YOU FEEL GOOD.
I FEEL DIZZY.
YES. YOU ARE LOVELY.
YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL.
KISS ME.
[GRRR]
OH!
AAH!
NO!
[RRRAAH]
WHERE'S
CAPTAIN KIRK?
TYREE,
THE FIRESTICK.
WHERE IS IT?
THERE!
I LEFT IT THERE.
THAT'S A FINE THING
TO LEAVE LYING AROUND.
SHOW US WHERE IT IS.
I DO NOT
WANT IT.
JIM!
JIM.
WHO HIT YOU?
NONA.
I BRING YOU VICTORY
FOR APELLA!
TYREE'S WOMAN.
SHE'S
A KAHN-UT-TU.
WE WON'T TRUST
THIS DIVISION TO APELLA.
TAKE ME TO HIM.
HE WILL HAVE
THE STRENGTH TO USE
THIS NEW WEAPON.
TOUCH ME AGAIN,
AND THIS SMALL BOX
WILL KILL YOU.
NO!
AAH!
NO, NO.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
MY PHASER.
SHE TOOK IT.
THIS WEAPON I BRING YOU
IS FAR GREATER
THAN YOUR FIRESTICK.
AAH!
NONA!
HILL PEOPLE!
IT'S A TRAP.
THE WOMAN'S
TRICKED US.
SHE'S DEAD.
I WANT
MORE OF THESE, KIRK.
MANY MORE!
YUTAN, TWO OF THOSE
WHO KILLED MY WIFE
HAVE ESCAPED.
TRACK THEM DOWN.
I WILL KILL THEM.
HERE.
TOMORROW...
IN THE PALM
OF HER HANDS.
WELL, YOU GOT
WHAT YOU WANTED.
NOT WHAT I WANTED,
BONES.
WHAT HAD TO BE.
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK, CAPTAIN.
I TRUST ALL HAS GONE WELL.
SPOCK,
ARE YOU ALIVE?
AN ILLOGICAL QUESTION,
DOCTOR,
SINCE OBVIOUSLY
YOU ARE HEARING MY VOICE.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
WHY I WAS WORRIED.
YOU CAN'T KILL
A COMPUTER.
MR. SPOCK, ASK SCOTTY
HOW LONG IT WOULD TAKE HIM
TO REPRODUCE
100 FLINTLOCKS.
I DIDN'T
GET THAT EXACTLY,
CAPTAIN.
100 WHAT?
100...
SERPENTS.
SERPENTS FOR
THE GARDEN OF EDEN.
WE'RE VERY TIRED,
MR. SPOCK.
BEAM US UP HOME.