THE READING'S GROWING
STRONGER, CAPTAIN.
COMING FROM A STAR SYSTEM
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
IT'S NOT
A SIGNAL, SIR.
IT DOES NOT SEEM
TO EVEN EXIST,
AND YET IT'S AFFECTING
ALL MY CHANNELS.
WELL?
SOMEONE OR SOMETHING
IS ATTEMPTING
TO ATTRACT OUR ATTENTION.
SOMEONE OR SOMETHING
HAS SUCCEEDED.
OUR DISTRESS SIGNAL RELAYS
HAVE BEEN ACTIVATED.
WE'VE BEEN GIVEN A DIRECTION
TO FOLLOW, BUT HOW?
WHAT'S CAUSING IT?
I DO NOT KNOW.
NOT EVEN A VULCAN CAN KNOW
THE UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE HUNDREDS
OF LIGHT YEARS PAST
WHERE ANY EARTH SHIP
HAS EVER EXPLORED.
PLANET DEAD AHEAD,
CAPTAIN.
BECOMING VISUAL.
CLASS "M" PLANET, CAPTAIN.
CLOSE TO EARTH CONDITIONS.
WITH TWO VERY IMPORTANT
EXCEPTIONS.
IT IS MUCH OLDER
THAN EARTH,
AND ABOUT A HALF MILLION
YEARS AGO,
ITS ATMOSPHERE
WAS TOTALLY RIPPED AWAY
BY SOME SORT OF CATACLYSM.
THE PLANET HAS EVIDENTLY
BEEN DEAD SINCE THEN.
SENSORS DETECT NO LIFE
OF ANY KIND.
ALL OF YOUR QUESTIONS
WILL BE ANSWERED IN TIME,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
ARE YOUR HAILING
FREQUENCIES OPEN?
NO, SIR.
I AM SARGON.
IT IS THE ENERGY
OF MY THOUGHTS
WHICH HAS TOUCHED
YOUR INSTRUMENTS
AND DIRECTED YOU HERE.
NOW WITH
THIS CLOSER DISTANCE
I CAN SPEAK TO YOU
AT LAST.
WHO ARE YOU, SARGON?
PLEASE ASSUME
A STANDARD ORBIT
ABOUT OUR PLANET,
CAPTAIN.
IS THAT A REQUEST OR DEMAND?
THE CHOICE IS YOURS.
I READ WHAT
IS IN YOUR MIND.
WORDS ARE UNNECESSARY.
THE PLANET IS DEAD.
THERE'S NO POSSIBILITY
OF LIFE THERE
AS WE UNDERSTAND LIFE.
AND I AM AS DEAD
AS MY PLANET.
DOES THAT FRIGHTEN YOU,
JAMES KIRK?
FOR IF IT DOES,
IF YOU LET
WHAT IS LEFT OF ME PERISH,
THEN ALL OF YOU,
MY CHILDREN,
ALL OF MANKIND
MUST PERISH, TOO.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4768.3.
THE ENTERPRISE IS IN ORBIT
ABOVE A PLANET
WHOSE SURFACE,
OUR SENSORS TELL US,
IS DEVOID OF ALL LIFE,
A WORLD
DESTROYED AND DEAD
FOR AT LEAST
A HALF MILLION YEARS,
YET FROM IT
COMES A VOICE,
THE ENERGY
OF PURE THOUGHT,
TELLING US SOMETHING
HAS SURVIVED HERE
FOR THOSE THOUSANDS
OF CENTURIES.
SINCE EXPLORATION AND CONTACT
WITH ALIEN INTELLIGENCE
IS OUR PRIMARY MISSION,
I'VE DECIDED TO RISK
THE POTENTIAL DANGERS
AND RESUME CONTACT.
LOG ENTRY OUT.
HOW LONG BEFORE
STARFLEET RECEIVES THAT?
OVER THREE WEEKS
AT THIS DISTANCE, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
GOT SOMETHING?
SENSORS REGISTERING
SOME FORM OF ENERGY
DEEP INSIDE THE PLANET.
YOUR PROBES HAVE
TOUCHED ME, MR. SPOCK.
READING ENERGY ONLY,
CAPTAIN.
NO LIFE FORMS.
I HAVE LOCKED
YOUR TRANSPORTER DEVICE
ON MY COORDINATES.
PLEASE COME TO US.
RESCUE US FROM OBLIVION.
COMING FROM DEEP UNDER
THE PLANET SURFACE, CAPTAIN,
UNDER AT LEAST 100 MILES
OF SOLID ROCK.
I WILL MAKE IT POSSIBLE
FOR YOUR TRANSPORTER
TO BEAM YOU THAT DEEP
BENEATH THE SURFACE.
HAVE NO FEAR.
READING A CHAMBER NOW.
OXYGEN-NITROGEN ATMOSPHERE,
SUITABLE FOR
HUMAN LIFE SUPPORT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HAVE DR. McCOY REPORT
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
IN 10 MINUTES WITH STANDARD
LANDING PARTY EQUIPMENT.
YES, SIR.
SPOCK--
CAPTAIN, I...
DO WISH TO INSPECT
WHATEVER THIS IS
THAT LIVED
THAT LONG AGO.
AND I WOULD LIKE
TO HAVE MY SCIENCE
OFFICER WITH ME
ON SOMETHING
AS UNUSUAL AS THIS,
BUT IT IS
FULL OF UNKNOWNS,
AND WE CAN'T RISK
BOTH OF US BEING
OFF THE SHIP.
ALL POWER
GONE, SIR.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
PERHAPS THIS SARGON
WOULD LIKE YOU
TO COME WITH US.
FASCINATING.
ALL NORMAL.
NO DAMAGE AT ALL.
I SEE.
WILL YOU TRANSPORT
DOWN WITH US,
MR. SPOCK?
EVIDENTLY, CAPTAIN.
MR. SULU,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
JIM, WHY NO
BRIEFING ON THIS?
I'D AT LEAST LIKE
TO KNOW WHAT WE'RE
GETTING INTO.
EASY. EASY, BONES.
AS LONG AS YOU KNOW
THAT THERE'S SOMETHING
DOWN THERE,
YOU KNOW
AS MUCH AS WE DO.
THE REST
IS ONLY GUESSES.
I DON'T
LIKE IT, SIR.
THE TRANSPORTER
COORDINATES
PRESET BY A...
BY AN ALIEN
OF SOME SORT.
YOU COULD MATERIALIZE
INSIDE SOLID ROCK.
INSIDE SOLID ROCK?
UNLIKELY.
THESE COORDINATES
CORRESPOND
WITH THE LOCATION
OF THE SUBTERRANEAN
CHAMBER.
I HAVE A FEELING
THAT THEY OR IT
COULD DESTROY US
JUST STANDING HERE
IF THEY OR IT
WANTED TO.
THEY OR IT?
WHO ARE YOU?
DR. ANNE MULHALL,
ASTRO-BIOLOGY.
WELL, I WAS ORDERED
TO REPORT HERE
FOR LANDING PARTY DUTY.
BY WHOM?
STRANGE. I'M NOT SURE.
WELL, I'M NOT
A LIAR, CAPTAIN.
I DID RECEIVE AN ORDER
TO REPORT HERE FOR DUTY.
I'M SURE
SHE DID, CAPTAIN,
JUST AS YOU
RECEIVED AN ORDER
TO BRING ME ALONG.
OH, YES.
LET'S GET BACK
TO THIS SOLID ROCK
BUSINESS.
JUST HOW MUCH ROCK
ARE WE GOING TO GO
THROUGH?
APPROXIMATELY
112.37 MILES,
DOCTOR.
MILES?
ARE YOU JOKING?
NO, WE'RE NOT.
LET'S GO.
PLEASE STAND READY.
I WILL OPERATE
YOUR CONTROLS.
DOCTOR...
IF YOU PREFER
TO STAY BEHIND...
NO.
NO, IF
I'D BE USEFUL,
AS LONG AS
YOU'RE GOING DOWN,
I MIGHT AS WELL
TAKE A MEDICAL LOOK
AT WHATEVER THIS IS.
[BEEPING]
CAPTAIN,
THE SECURITY GUARDS.
[BEEP BEEP]
KIRK HERE.
[SCOTTY]
CAN YOU READ ME,
CAPTAIN?
YES, SCOTTY, AND I
SHOULDN'T BE ABLE TO
THIS DEEP
INSIDE THE PLANET,
BUT PERHAPS THAT'S BEEN
ARRANGED FOR US, TOO.
IS THE SECURITY GUARD
UP THERE?
THEY'RE FINE, CAPTAIN.
THEY JUST DIDN'T
DEMATERIALIZE.
I DON'T LIKE IT, SIR.
NO PROBLEM YET.
MAINTAIN ALERT.
KIRK OUT.
ATMOSPHERE REPORT,
CAPTAIN.
A FRACTION
RICHER IN OXYGEN
THAN USUAL FOR US,
BUT OTHERWISE NORMAL.
THIS VAULT WAS
CONSTRUCTED ABOUT
A HALF MILLION YEARS AGO.
ABOUT THE SAME TIME,
THE PLANET SURFACE
WAS DESTROYED,
IF OUR SENSOR READINGS
ARE ACCURATE.
COMPOSITION OF WALLS?
THEY'RE AN ALLOY
OR SUBSTANCE
COMPLETELY
UNKNOWN TO ME,
MUCH STRONGER AND HARDER
THAN ANYTHING
I'VE MEASURED BEFORE.
ALL READINGS ARE OFF
THE SCALE, CAPTAIN.
THE AIR SEEMS FRESH.
IT MUST BE
RECIRCULATED SOMEHOW.
IS THAT FOR US
OR DOES IT NEED
FRESH AIR?
WELCOME.
I AM SARGON.
SARGON...
WOULD IT HARM YOU
IF I...
YOU MAY USE YOUR
TRICORDER, MR. SPOCK.
YOUR READINGS
WILL SHOW ENERGY
BUT NO SUBSTANCE.
SEALED IN
THIS RECEPTACLE
IS THE ESSENCE
OF MY MIND.
PURE ENERGY.
MATTER WITHOUT FORM.
IMPOSSIBLE.
BUT YOU ONCE HAD
A BODY OF SOME TYPE?
A BODY MUCH AS YOURS,
MY CHILDREN,
ALTHOUGH OUR MINDS WERE
INFINITELY GREATER.
THAT'S TWICE YOU'VE
REFERRED TO US
AS "MY CHILDREN."
BECAUSE IT IS POSSIBLE
YOU ARE OUR DESCENDANTS,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
SIX THOUSAND CENTURIES AGO,
OUR VESSELS WERE
COLONIZING THIS GALAXY,
JUST AS YOUR OWN STARSHIPS
HAVE NOW BEGUN TO EXPLORE
THAT VASTNESS.
AS YOU NOW LEAVE YOUR OWN SEED
ON DISTANT PLANETS,
SO WE LEFT
OUR SEED BEHIND US.
PERHAPS YOUR OWN LEGENDS
OF AN ADAM AND AN EVE
WERE TWO OF OUR TRAVELERS.
OUR BELIEFS
AND OUR STUDIES
INDICATE THAT LIFE
ON OUR PLANET EARTH
EVOLVED INDEPENDENTLY.
THAT WOULD TEND, HOWEVER,
TO EXPLAIN CERTAIN ELEMENTS
OF VULCAN PREHISTORY.
IN EITHER CASE,
I DO NOT KNOW.
IT WAS SO LONG AGO,
AND THE RECORDS OF OUR TRAVELS
WERE LOST IN THE CATACLYSM
WHICH WE LOOSENED
UPON OURSELVES.
A WAR?
A STRUGGLE FOR SUCH GOALS
AND THE UNLEASHING
OF SUCH POWER
THAT YOU COULD
NOT COMPREHEND.
THEN PERHAPS
YOUR INTELLIGENCE
WASN'T SO GREAT, SARGON.
WE FACED
A SIMILAR CRISIS
IN OUR EARLY
NUCLEAR AGE.
WE FOUND THE WISDOM
NOT TO DESTROY
OURSELVES.
AND WE SURVIVED
OUR PRIMITIVE
NUCLEAR ERA, MY SON.
BUT THERE COMES
TO ALL RACES
AN ULTIMATE CRISIS
WHICH YOU HAVE
YET TO FACE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ONE DAY OUR MINDS
BECAME SO POWERFUL,
WE DARED THINK
OF OURSELVES AS GODS.
YOU SAID
YOU WANTED OUR HELP.
WHAT IS IT YOU WISH?
JUST A MOMENT,
DOCTOR.
I...
AM...
SARGON.
WHERE'S OUR CAPTAIN?
WHERE'S JIM KIRK?
HE IS...UNHARMED.
I...HAVE TAKEN HIS BODY
TO DEMONSTRATE.
I WON'T
GO ALONG WITH THIS.
BACK TO WHERE YOU WERE,
SARGON,
OR WHATEVER YOU ARE.
AND IF HE REFUSES,
DOCTOR,
WHAT DO YOU PROPOSE
TO DO WITH YOUR PHASER?
THAT IS STILL
JIM'S BODY.
LUNGS FILLED
WITH AIR AGAIN.
TO SEE AGAIN.
HEART...PUMPING.
ARTERIES SURGING
BLOOD AGAIN.
AFTER A HALF
A MILLION YEARS.
TO BE AGAIN.
YOUR CAPTAIN HAS AN
EXCELLENT BODY, DR. McCOY.
I COMPLIMENT YOU BOTH
ON THE CONDITION
IN WHICH YOU MAINTAINED IT.
WHAT ARE
YOUR PLANS FOR IT?
CAN YOU EXCHANGE PLACES
AGAIN WHEN YOU WISH?
HAVE NO FEAR.
YOUR CAPTAIN
IS QUITE UNHARMED,
ALTHOUGH
HIS MIND GENERATES
INSUFFICIENT ENERGY
FOR HIM TO SPEAK
FROM THERE AS I DO.
DOCTOR?
YES, I HAVE
THE SAME READINGS.
ARE YOU AWARE
OF WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO HIS BODY--
HEART ACTION DOUBLED,
TEMPERATURE 104 DEGREES?
HE'LL DIE IF YOU DON'T
LEAVE HIS BODY SOON.
WHAT IS IT YOU
WANT OF US?
IN THE NEXT ROOM,
THERE ARE
OTHER RECEPTACLES--
THE OTHER TWO OF US
THAT SURVIVED.
YOU, DR. ANNE MULHALL,
AND YOU, MR. SPOCK,
WE REQUIRE
YOUR BODIES ALSO.
WE MUST HAVE
CAPTAIN KIRK...
AND YOU...
SO THAT
WE MAY LIVE AGAIN.
EVEN FOR US,
A HALF MILLION YEARS
WAS ALMOST TOO LONG
TO WAIT.
TWO OTHERS
STILL SURVIVE--
HENOCH...
AND THALASSA.
THALASSA,
MY THALASSA.
I AM PLEASED
YOU SURVIVED.
FORGIVE ME.
IT HAS BEEN
SO VERY LONG.
WHEN THE
STRUGGLE CAME
WHICH DEVASTATED
YOUR PLANET--
ONLY THE BEST MINDS
WERE CHOSEN
TO SURVIVE--
THALASSA,
MY WIFE, AS YOU
MAY HAVE GUESSED.
HENOCH,
FROM THE OTHER SIDE.
REALIZING
OUR MISTAKE,
WE ATTEMPTED
TO PERPETUATE
BOTH SIDES.
WE BUILT
THIS CHAMBER HERE
IN ORDER TO
PRESERVE OUR ESSENCE
IN THIS FASHION.
FASCINATING.
WE KNEW THE SEED
THAT WE HAD PLANTED
ON OTHER PLANETS
WOULD TAKE ROOT,
THAT ONE DAY YOU WOULD
BUILD VESSELS AS WE DID,
AND ONE DAY YOU WOULD
COME HERE.
THESE OTHERS,
THEY WERE STORED
DIFFERENTLY
THAN YOU,
BUT IT WAS
YOUR TASK
TO REMAIN
IN THE RECEPTACLE
OUT THERE...
AND SEARCH THE HEAVENS
WITH MY MIND,
PROBING, WAITING, PROBING.
AND THEN ONE DAY
MY MIND TOUCHED YOUR VESSEL
AND BROUGHT YOU HERE.
SO YOU COULD STEAL
OUR BODIES FROM US?
TO STEAL?
TO TAKE THEM FROM YOU?
NO, NO, MY CHILDREN,
YOU MISUNDERSTAND.
WE MEAN ONLY THAT YOU SHOULD
LEND US YOUR BODIES
FOR A SHORT TIME.
AND DESTROY THEM,
JUST AS YOU'RE BURNING
THAT ONE UP NOW.
HEARTBEAT--262, SPOCK.
ENTIRE METABOLIC RATE
CORRESPONDINGLY HIGH.
I WILL RETURN
YOUR CAPTAIN TO YOU
BEFORE THE BODY LIMIT
HAS BEEN REACHED.
OUR BODIES, SARGON,
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
TO BUILD.
TO BUILD HUMANOID ROBOTS.
WE MUST BORROW YOUR BODIES
LONG ENOUGH
TO HAVE THE USE OF
YOUR HANDS, YOUR FINGERS.
THEN YOU INTEND
TO CONSTRUCT
MECHANICAL BODIES,
MOVE YOUR MINDS
INTO THEM,
AND THEN RETURN
OUR BODIES TO US.
WE HAVE ENGINEERS,
TECHNICIANS.
WHY CAN'T THEY BUILD
YOUR ROBOTS FOR YOU?
NO. OUR METHODS,
OUR SKILLS...
ARE FAR BEYOND
YOUR ABILITIES.
IT IS TIME.
IS IT YOU, JIM?
GOOD. HIS METABOLIC RATE
IS BACK TO NORMAL.
CAPTAIN, DO YOU KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED?
DO YOU REMEMBER
ANY PART OF IT?
YES. SARGON
BORROWED MY BODY.
I WAS FLOATING
IN TIME AND SPACE.
HE DOESN'T APPEAR
TO BE HARMED.
PHYSICALLY, ANYWAY.
SPOCK...
I REMEMBER.
WHEN SARGON AND I
EXCHANGED,
AS WE PASSED
EACH OTHER,
FOR AN INSTANT,
WE WERE ONE.
I KNOW HIM NOW.
I KNOW WHAT HE IS
AND WHAT HE WANTS,
AND I DON'T FEAR HIM.
THAT'S THE MOST RIDICULOUS
STATEMENT I'VE EVER HEARD.
AN ALIEN PRACTICALLY
HIJACKS YOUR BODY
AND THEN CORKS YOU
INTO A BOTTLE, AND YOU--
I'M AFRAID THAT
I MUST AGREE
WITH DR. McCOY.
YOU COULD BE SUFFERING
FROM A FORM OF FALSE
EUPHORIA.
SARGON.
I UNDERSTAND, MY SON.
GO TO YOUR VESSEL.
ALL WHO ARE INVOLVED
MUST AGREE TO THIS.
AFTER ALL THESE CENTURIES,
WE CAN WAIT
A FEW MORE HOURS.
WHAT IF WE SHOULD
DECIDE AGAINST YOU?
THEN YOU MAY GO
AS FREELY AS YOU CAME.
YOU'RE GOING TO WHAT?
ARE THEY ALL RIGHT
IN THE HEAD, DOCTOR?
NO COMMENT.
A SIMPLE TRANSFERENCE--
THEIR MINDS AND OURS.
QUITE SIMPLE.
HAPPENS EVERY DAY.
SCOTTY, I NEED
YOUR APPROVAL, TOO,
SINCE YOU'LL BE
WORKING WITH THEM,
FURNISHING THEM ALL
THEY NEED TO MAKE
THE ANDROID ROBOTS.
YOU WON'T BE WORKING
WITH THEM.
YOU'LL BE WORKING
WITH US--OUR BODIES.
THEY'LL BE INSIDE US,
AND WE'LL BE--
IT ALL SEEMS
RATHER INDECENT TO ME.
I'M NOT SO CERTAIN
OF THAT, DOCTOR.
IT IS SCIENTIFICALLY
FASCINATING.
ONCE INSIDE THEIR
MECHANICAL BODIES,
ENGINEER,
THEY CAN
LEAVE THIS PLANET,
TRAVEL BACK WITH US.
WITH THEIR KNOWLEDGE,
MANKIND COULD LEAP AHEAD
10,000 YEARS.
BONES, THEY'LL SHOW US
MEDICAL ADVANCES,
MIRACLES YOU NEVER
DREAMED POSSIBLE.
SCOTTY,
ENGINEERING ADVANCES--
VESSELS THIS SIZE
WITH ENGINES
THE SIZE OF WALNUTS.
ACH! YOU'RE JOKING.
NO, HE'S NOT.
THEY'RE GIANTS,
AND WE'RE INSECTS
BESIDE THEM.
THEY COULD DESTROY US
WITHOUT MEANING TO.
AND ALL HE WANTS
IS OUR CAPTAIN'S BODY
AND OUR
SECOND IN COMMAND, TOO.
COINCIDENCE?
THEY SELECTED US AS
THE MOST COMPATIBLE BODIES.
WHAT'S YOUR ATTITUDE
ON THAT, DOCTOR?
WELL, IF WE ALL AGREE,
I'M WILLING TO HOST
THALASSA'S MIND.
I'M A SCIENTIST.
THE OPPORTUNITY IS
AN EXTRAORDINARY ONE
FOR EXPERIMENTATION,
OBSERVATION.
A STARSHIP ENGINE
THE SIZE OF A WALNUT?
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
BUT I DON'T SUPPOSE
THERE'D BE ANY HARM
IN LOOKING OVER
DIAGRAMS ON IT.
BONES...
YOU COULD STOP ALL THIS
BY SAYING NO.
THAT'S WHY I CALLED YOU ALL
HERE TOGETHER.
WE'LL ALL BE
DEEPLY INVOLVED.
IT MUST BE
UNANIMOUS.
THEN I'LL STILL WANT
ONE QUESTION ANSWERED
TO MY SATISFACTION--
WHY?
NOT A LIST OF
POSSIBLE MIRACLES,
BUT A SIMPLE BASIC
UNDERSTANDABLE "WHY"
THAT OVERRIDES
ALL DANGER.
AND LET'S NOT
KID OURSELVES
THAT THERE IS
NO POTENTIAL DANGER
IN THIS.
THEY USED TO SAY
IF MAN COULD FLY,
HE'D HAVE WINGS.
BUT HE DID FLY.
HE DISCOVERED HE HAD TO.
DO YOU WISH THAT
THE FIRST APOLLO MISSION
HADN'T REACHED THE MOON
OR THAT WE HADN'T
GONE ON TO MARS AND
THEN TO THE NEAREST STAR?
THAT'S LIKE SAYING
YOU WISH THAT YOU STILL
OPERATED WITH SCALPELS
AND SEWED YOUR PATIENTS UP
WITH CATGUT
LIKE YOUR GREAT-
GREAT-GREAT-
GREAT-GRANDFATHER
USED TO.
I'M IN COMMAND.
I COULD ORDER THIS.
BUT I'M NOT...
BECAUSE...
DR. McCOY IS RIGHT
IN POINTING OUT
THE ENORMOUS DANGER POTENTIAL
IN ANY CONTACT WITH LIFE
AND INTELLIGENCE
AS FANTASTICALLY
ADVANCED AS THIS.
BUT I MUST POINT OUT
THAT THE POSSIBILITIES,
THE POTENTIAL FOR
KNOWLEDGE AND ADVANCEMENT
IS EQUALLY GREAT.
RISK.
RISK IS OUR BUSINESS.
THAT'S WHAT THIS STARSHIP
IS ALL ABOUT.
THAT'S WHY
WE'RE ABOARD HER.
YOU MAY DISSENT
WITHOUT PREJUDICE.
DO I HEAR A NEGATIVE VOTE?
ENGINEER...
STAND BY TO BEAM ABOARD
THREE RECEPTACLES.
THE EXTREME POWER
OF THE ALIEN MIND
WILL DRIVE
THE HEART ACTION
DANGEROUSLY HIGH.
THE BODY FUNCTIONS
WILL RACE MANY TIMES
THEIR NORMAL METABOLISM,
SO WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO MONITOR THIS
VERY CAREFULLY.
YES, SIR.
WELL, I GUESS
WE'RE ABOUT AS READY
AS WE'LL EVER BE, JIM.
READY, SARGON.
THE TRANSFERENCE...
IS COMPLETE.
HMM...
METABOLIC RATE IS DOUBLED
AND RISING, DOCTOR.
HELLO.
OH, YOU ARE
A LOVELY FEMALE.
A PLEASANT SIGHT
TO WAKE UP TO
AFTER
HALF A MILLION YEARS.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
I'D FORGOTTEN
WHAT IT FELT LIKE...
EVEN TO BREATHE AGAIN.
SARGON?
HERE.
IN THIS BODY.
I AM NOT DISPLEASED,
MY HUSBAND.
YOUR BODY
IS NOT UNLIKE THAT
WHICH WAS YOUR OWN.
AND I, TOO...
AM PLEASED,
BELOVED.
AFTER SO LONG...
SO VERY LONG.
YES.
THIS IS AN EXCELLENT BODY,
DOCTOR.
I SEEM TO HAVE RECEIVED
THE BEST OF THE THREE.
STRENGTH, HEARING,
EYESIGHT,
ALL FAR ABOVE
YOUR HUMAN NORMS.
I'M SURPRISED THE VULCANS
NEVER CONQUERED YOUR RACE.
VULCANS WORSHIP PEACE
ABOVE ALL, HENOCH.
YES, OF COURSE,
JUST AS WE DO, DOCTOR.
NURSE!
DOCTOR.
HENOCH, YOU'D BETTER
GET BACK TO BED, TOO.
IT WILL BE UNNECESSARY,
DOCTOR.
THIS VULCAN BODY
IS ACCUSTOMED TO
THE HIGHER METABOLISM.
SARGON, IT WON'T WORK.
YOU'VE GOT TO GET OUT
BEFORE YOU KILL THEM!
WE WILL VACATE AT ONCE
UNTIL YOU CAN ADMINISTER
A METABOLIC REDUCTION
INJECTION.
A WHAT?
I'LL PREPARE
THE FORMULA, SARGON.
HENOCH...
YOUR CONDITION?
I CAN CONTINUE
IN THIS BODY
FOR SEVERAL HOURS.
FORTUNATE.
WE WILL...
VACATE AT ONCE.
THIS WOMAN WILL ASSIST ME.
YOU WILL TAKE ME TO
YOUR PHARMACOLOGY LABORATORY.
BONES...
WHAT...
IT WAS CLOSE, JIM.
YOU BOTH BARELY
GOT BACK ALIVE.
UNLESS THE FORMULA
WORKS,
WE CAN'T RISK IT
AGAIN.
NOW, THIS FORMULA WILL
REDUCE THE HEART ACTION
AND THE BODILY FUNCTIONS
TO NORMAL.
WHILE THE BODIES
ARE OCCUPIED,
YOU WILL ADMINISTER
ONE INJECTION OF 10ccs
EACH HOUR.
I UNDERSTAND.
THIS HYPO YOU WILL
CODE MARK FOR THALASSA.
AND THIS ONE YOU WILL
CODE MARK...FOR ME.
YES, SIR.
THIS ONE
YOU WILL ADMINISTER
TO CAPTAIN KIRK
WHILE SARGON
IS IN HIS BODY.
THIS HYPO
DOES NOT CONTAIN
THE SAME FORMULA.
NO. THAT'S CORRECT.
BUT SINCE I WILL
ARRANGE FOR YOU
TO ADMINISTER
EACH OF THE INJECTIONS,
NO ONE ELSE
WILL NOTICE.
BUT WITHOUT
THE SAME FORMULA,
CAPTAIN KIRK WILL DIE.
WHAT WERE YOU SAYING?
I...
I-I-I WAS...
I WANTED TO SAY SOMETHING.
I'VE FORGOTTEN
WHAT IT WAS.
YES. WELL,
YOU WERE ABOUT TO SAY
THAT YOU WATCHED ME
PREPARE THE FORMULA
AND FILL
EACH OF THE HYPOS.
YES, THAT...THAT WAS IT.
I WILL INFORM DR. McCOY
THAT EACH IS
PROPERLY FILLED
FOR EACH PATIENT.
VERY GOOD.
YOU SEE, SARGON
WOULD NOT PERMIT ME
TO KEEP THIS BODY.
IT IS THEREFORE
NECESSARY FOR YOU
TO KILL YOUR CAPTAIN
SO THAT SARGON
WILL DIE WITH HIM.
[DR. McCOY]
ENTERPRISE MEDICAL LOG,
STARDATE 4769.1.
THREE ALIEN MINDS
NOW INHABIT THE BODIES
OF CAPTAIN KIRK,
SCIENCE OFFICER SPOCK,
AND DR. ANNE MULHALL.
AS PLANNED,
THE CONSTRUCTION OF
ANDROID ROBOTS IS UNDERWAY.
ALL IS PROCEEDING
AS EXPECTED...
AND AS PROMISED.
I CAN FIND
NO REASON FOR CONCERN,
BUT YET I AM FILLED
WITH FOREBODING.
SARGON, I REMEMBER
A DAY LONG AGO.
WE SAT BESIDE
A SILVER LAKE.
THE AIR WAS SCENTED WITH
THE FLOWERS OF OUR PLANET.
I REMEMBER.
YOU HELD MY HAND...
LIKE THIS.
I THINK IT BEST
NOT TO REMEMBER
SO WELL.
IN TWO DAYS, YOU'LL HAVE
HANDS OF YOUR OWN AGAIN,
THALASSA--
MECHANICALLY EFFICIENT
AND QUITE HUMAN-LOOKING.
ANDROID ROBOT HANDS,
OF COURSE.
HANDS WITHOUT FEELING.
ENJOY THE TASTE OF LIFE
WHILE YOU CAN.
OUR MINDS
WILL HAVE SURVIVED.
AND AS ANDROIDS,
WE CAN MOVE AMONG
THE PEOPLE WHO DO LIVE,
TEACHING THEM,
HELPING THEM NOT
TO MAKE THE ERRORS WE DID.
WHAT IS IT,
SARGON?
NOTHING.
OUR NEXT INJECTION
WILL RENOVATE ME.
DO NOT BE CONCERNED.
NURSE, HOW ARE THE LAST
METABOLIC READINGS
ON OUR PATIENTS?
YOU'LL FIND THEM
EXCELLENT, DOCTOR.
WELL WITHIN NORMAL.
IS SOMETHING WRONG,
MISS CHAPEL?
UH...YES.
I, UH...
I HAD...
SOMETHING TO SAY.
I...CAN'T SEEM
TO REMEMBER.
REGARDING
OUR PATIENTS?
UM...YES.
THAT MUST BE IT.
UM...
I AM SO PLEASED
THE WAY THEY ARE
RESPONDING, DOCTOR.
THE FORMULA'S
WORKING PERFECTLY.
YOU LOOK TIRED,
MISS CHAPEL.
PERHAPS
YOU'D CARE FOR ME
TO ADMINISTER
THE LAST FEW INJECTIONS.
TIRED?
WELL, NOT
AT ALL, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU
FOR ASKING.
THANK YOU.
HAVE YOU PREPARED
THE NEGATON HYDROCOILS
FOR THE DRAWING
SARGON SUPPLIED?
FOR ALL THE GOOD
IT'LL DO YOU.
IT'S A FANCY NAME,
BUT HOW WILL
SOMETHING THAT LOOKS
LIKE A DROP OF JELLY
MAKE THIS THING WORK?
YOU'LL NEED MICROGEARS
AND SOME FORM OF
PULLEY THAT DOES
WHAT A MUSCLE DOES.
THAT WOULD BE
HIGHLY INEFFICIENT.
I TELL YOU, LADY,
THIS THING WON'T WORK.
IT WILL HAVE TWICE
THE STRENGTH AND AGILITY
OF YOUR BODY, ENGINEER,
AND IT WILL LAST
A THOUSAND YEARS.
THAT IS, ASSUMING
YOU'LL STOP
WASTING YOUR TIME
AND ALLOW US
TO COMPLETE IT.
A THOUSAND-YEAR PRISON,
THALASSA.
AND WHEN IT WEARS OUT,
WE'LL BUILD ANOTHER ONE,
AND WE'LL
LOCK OURSELVES INTO IT
FOR ANOTHER
THOUSAND YEARS...
AND ANOTHER...
AND ANOTHER.
SARGON HAS
CLOSED HIS MIND
TO A BETTER WAY...
WITH THESE BODIES.
THEY'RE NOT OURS,
HENOCH.
WHEN YOU AWOKE
IN THIS BODY, THALASSA,
YOU SAID HOW GOOD IT WAS
TO BREATHE AGAIN,
TO HAVE EYES,
AND TO SEE AGAIN,
TO FEEL...
TO LIVE AND FEEL AGAIN,
THALASSA.
JUST THINK HOW MUCH
WE CAN DO FOR MANKIND.
ARE THESE BODIES
TOO MUCH TO ASK FOR
IN RETURN?
WOULD YOU PREFER THIS?
NO.
I'M BEGINNING
TO HATE IT.
SICKBAY.
SICKBAY. McCOY.
SARGON HERE, McCOY.
I'M IN YOUR...
DECK 6 BRIEFING ROOM.
YOU SOUND TERRIBLE.
WAIT THERE FOR ME.
SARGON, WHAT IS IT?
NOTHING OF IMPORTANCE.
FATIGUE, PERHAPS.
HENOCH'S FORMULA.
YES. I WANTED TO BE CERTAIN
THERE WAS NO ERROR.
FORMULA...
IS CORRECT.
DON'T BE CONCERNED.
IT IS
AN EXCELLENT BODY.
THERE. YOU SEE?
I FEEL BETTER ALREADY.
IN TIME, OUR HOST BODY
WILL BECOME ACCUSTOMED
TO US, HUSBAND.
INJECTIONS WILL
NO LONGER BE NECESSARY.
THAT WILL TAKE MONTHS,
PERHAPS YEARS.
WE HAVEN'T THAT CHOICE,
THALASSA.
HUSBAND...
FEEL THE TOUCH
OF MY HAND, HUSBAND.
NO, BELOVED.
IF WE
TORMENT OURSELVES--
BELOVED--
WHAT WILL THAT WORD
MEAN TO A MACHINE?
OUR THOUGHTS
WILL INTERTWINE.
WILL THEY, HUSBAND?
WILL THEY INTERTWINE
LIKE THIS?
CAN TWO MINDS
PRESS CLOSE LIKE THIS?
CAN ROBOT LIPS DO THIS?
SARGON...
WHAT IS IT?
HYPO.
DOCTOR, HELP HIM.
HE'S DEAD.
[DR. McCOY]
MEDICAL LOG,
STARDATE 4770.3.
DO I LIST ONE DEATH
OR TWO?
WHEN KIRK'S BODY DIED,
SARGON WAS TOO FAR DISTANT
FROM HIS RECEPTACLE
TO TRANSFER BACK.
SARGON IS DEAD.
BUT IS CAPTAIN KIRK DEAD?
HIS BODY IS,
BUT HIS CONSCIOUSNESS
IS STILL IN THE RECEPTACLE
INTO WHICH
IT WAS TRANSFERRED EARLIER.
ALL HIS VITAL ORGANS
ARE NOW WORKING, DOCTOR.
YES. WE CAN KEEP THEM
GOING FOR A FEW WEEKS
OR A MONTH,
FOR ALL THE GOOD
IT'LL DO.
WHY PRETEND TO WORK
ON THAT THING, HENOCH?
YOU KNOW YOU
NEVER INTENDED
TO LEAVE SPOCK'S BODY.
THIS IS YOUR NEW HOME,
THALASSA.
ONCE OCCUPIED,
I'LL ADD FEMALE FEATURES
AND SOME TEXTURING.
YOU NO DOUBT WANT
THE MECHANISM
TO AT LEAST APPEAR
TO BE A WOMAN.
[BEEPING]
IT IS READY,
THALASSA.
NO!
YOU HAVE NO EXCUSE
TO KEEP THE REAL BODY
ANY LONGER.
SARGON
WOULD'VE REQUIRED
THAT YOU ENTER
THE MECHANISM IMMEDIATELY.
I CANNOT LIVE
IN THAT THING.
DOCTOR.
YES?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SAVE YOUR
CAPTAIN KIRK?
BUT YOU SAID
THAT WAS IMPOSSIBLE.
WE HAVE MANY POWERS
SARGON DID NOT
PERMIT US TO USE.
HE THOUGHT THEM
TOO TEMPTING TO US.
THIS BODY PLEASES ME.
I INTEND TO KEEP IT.
I SEE.
AND HENOCH INTENDS
TO KEEP SPOCK'S BODY,
OF COURSE.
HENOCH'S PLANS
ARE HIS OWN AFFAIR.
I WISH ONLY TO EXIST
IN PEACE
AS A LIVING WOMAN.
IF YOU'RE
ASKING MY APPROVAL--
I REQUIRE ONLY
YOUR SILENCE.
ONLY YOU AND I
WILL KNOW
THAT DR. MULHALL
HAS NOT RETURNED
TO HER BODY.
ISN'T THAT WORTH
YOUR CAPTAIN'S LIFE?
DOCTOR...
WE CAN TAKE
WHAT WE WISH.
NEITHER YOU,
THIS SHIP,
NOR ALL YOUR WORLDS
HAVE THE POWER
TO STOP US.
NEITHER JIM NOR I
CAN TRADE A BODY
WE DON'T OWN.
IT HAPPENS TO BELONG
TO A YOUNG WOMAN.
WHO YOU HARDLY KNOW.
ALMOST A STRANGER
TO YOU.
I WILL NOT
PEDDLE FLESH!
I'M A PHYSICIAN.
A PHYSICIAN?
IN CONTRAST
TO WHAT WE ARE,
YOU ARE A PRANCING,
SAVAGE MEDICINE MAN.
YOU DARE DEFY ONE
YOU SHOULD BE
ON YOUR KNEES
WORSHIPPING?
I COULD DESTROY YOU
WITH A SINGLE THOUGHT.
STOP!
SARGON WAS RIGHT.
TEMPTATIONS WITHIN
A LIVING BODY ARE TOO GREAT.
FORGIVE ME.
I AM PLEASED,
MY BELOVED.
IT IS GOOD YOU HAVE
FOUND THE TRUTH YOURSELF.
SARGON?
WHERE ARE YOU?
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
DESTROYED BY HENOCH.
I HAVE POWER EVEN HENOCH
DOES NOT SUSPECT, BELOVED.
YES.
YES, I SEE.
I...
I UNDERSTAND.
JUST AS WE WOULD HAVE
PLACED OUR CONSCIOUSNESS
WITHIN ROBOTS,
SARGON HAS PLACED HIS
INTO YOUR VESSEL.
DOCTOR.
DOCTOR,
LEAVE US.
SARGON HAS A PLAN.
WE HAVE MUCH WORK TO DO.
THIS IS SICKBAY.
GET ME--
NURSE CHAPEL,
WHAT IN THE DEVIL--
JIM?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, I'M FINE,
BONES.
THALASSA?
SHE IS...
NOW WITH SARGON, DOCTOR.
I...
I'M ANNE MULHALL,
BACK IN MY OWN BODY.
JIM, THE RECEPTACLES!
SPOCK'S CONSCIOUSNESS
WAS IN ONE OF THEM.
IT WAS NECESSARY.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THERE IS NO SPOCK
TO RETURN TO HIS BODY.
YOU'VE KILLED
A LOYAL OFFICER,
YOUR BEST FRIEND.
BONES, PREPARE A HYPO--
THE FASTEST,
DEADLIEST POISON
TO VULCANS.
SPOCK'S CONSCIOUSNESS
IS GONE.
WE MUST KILL HIS BODY,
THE THING IN IT.
AAH!
MUST I MAKE AN EXAMPLE
OF YOU, TOO, HELM?
PAIN, CAPTAIN?
AND YOU, MY DEAR?
FORTUNATELY, DOCTOR,
I KNOW EVERY THOUGHT
OF EVERY MIND AROUND ME.
SEE?
TAKE THE HYPO FROM HIM.
AND INJECT HIM
WITH IT.
YOU FOOLS.
I'LL SIMPLY TRANSFER
TO ANOTHER PLACE,
ANOTHER BODY.
SARGON!
NO, SARGON, PLEASE.
LET ME...
TRANSFER...
SPOCK.
MY FRIEND SPOCK.
IF THERE'D ONLY BEEN
ANOTHER WAY.
I COULD NOT ALLOW
YOUR SACRIFICE
OF ONE SO CLOSE TO YOU.
JIM.
YOU'RE ALIVE.
THERE WAS ENOUGH POISON
IN THAT HYPO
TO KILL 10 VULCANS.
NO, DOCTOR,
I ALLOWED YOU TO
BELIEVE THAT TO BE TRUE
SO THAT HENOCH WOULD
READ YOUR THOUGHTS
AND BELIEVE IT ALSO.
SARGON.
IT SEEMS, DOCTOR,
THE INJECTION
WAS ONLY ENOUGH TO
CAUSE UNCONSCIOUSNESS.
BUT HENOCH BELIEVED
AND FLED THE BODY.
HE IS DESTROYED.
BUT YOUR VESSEL
WAS DESTROYED, TOO.
WHERE WAS YOUR
CONSCIOUSNESS KEPT?
THE PLACE HENOCH WOULD
LEAST SUSPECT, CAPTAIN.
THAT IS WHY
I WAS SUMMONED TO
THE SICKBAY, DOCTOR.
MR. SPOCK'S
CONSCIOUSNESS
WAS PLACED IN ME.
WE SHARED
CONSCIOUSNESS
TOGETHER.
WE NOW KNOW
WE CANNOT PERMIT OURSELVES
TO EXIST IN YOUR WORLD,
MY CHILDREN.
THALASSA AND I MUST NOW
ALSO DEPART INTO OBLIVION.
IS THERE ANY WAY
WE CAN HELP YOU, SARGON?
YES, MY SON.
YOU CAN ALLOW
THALASSA AND ME
TO SHARE YOUR BODIES AGAIN.
A LAST MOMENT TOGETHER.
OBLIVION TOGETHER
DOES NOT FRIGHTEN ME,
BELOVED.
PROMISE
WE'LL BE TOGETHER.
I PROMISE...
BELOVED.
TOGETHER FOREVER.
FOREVER...BELOVED.
FOREVER.
WELL,
I'M SURE THAT, UH...
SARGON APPRECIATED
YOUR COOPERATION,
DR. MULHALL.
YES. I WAS, UH...
HAPPY TO COOPERATE,
CAPTAIN.
IT WAS BEAUTIFUL.