PASSING
OUTER PLANET ZEON.
WE WANT
THE INNER ONE, EKOS.
PLOT A STANDARD ORBIT,
MR. CHEKOV, AND TAKE US IN.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TRY TO RAISE JOHN GILL
ON STARFLEET
COMMUNICATIONS.
AYE, AYE,
SIR.
STARFLEET'S
BEEN TRYING
FOR SIX MONTHS.
IF HE'S STILL
ALIVE,
ISN'T IT UNLIKELY
THAT HE'D RECEIVE
US NOW?
I DON'T KNOW, BONES.
WE'RE HERE TO FIND OUT
WHAT'S HAPPENED
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW.
I NEVER MET JOHN GILL,
BUT I STUDIED
EARTH HISTORY FROM
THE TEXT HE PREPARED.
I KNEW HIM VERY WELL.
HE WAS MY INSTRUCTOR
AT THE ACADEMY.
WHAT IMPRESSED ME MOST
WAS HIS TREATMENT
OF EARTH HISTORY
AS CAUSES AND MOTIVATIONS
RATHER THAN DATES
AND EVENTS.
[UHURA]
CAPTAIN,
NO RESPONSE ON ANY
STARFLEET CHANNEL.
SPACECRAFT APPROACHING
FROM INNER PLANET.
FROM EKOS?
YES, BUT IT MUST BE
A ZEON SHIP.
THE ZEONS DO HAVE
A CRUDE INTERPLANETARY
CAPABILITY.
REACTION POWERED,
A SMALL ROCKET.
IT IS ON
AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
THAT WOULD MEAN
IT HAS SOPHISTICATED
DETECTION DEVICES
WHICH NEITHER ZEON
NOR EKOS SHOULD HAVE.
HAVE YOU RAISED ANYONE,
LIEUTENANT?
NOTHING, SIR.
CAPTAIN, IT IS
AN UNMANNED PROBE
WHICH SEEMS TO BE
CARRYING A WARHEAD.
STAND BY PHASERS.
PHASERS READY.
RANGE, MR. CHEKOV?
2,000 KILOMETERS.
CLOSING FAST.
FIRE.
FASCINATING.
A THERMONUCLEAR
WARHEAD.
THAT'S GENERATIONS AHEAD
OF WHERE THESE PEOPLE
SHOULD BE TECHNICALLY.
HOW DID THEY
MANAGE THAT?
MAYBE THEY HAD HELP.
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE,
IT'S FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE
NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
GO TO MAXIMUM ORBIT.
TAKE US OUT OF RANGE
OF THEIR DETECTION
DEVICES.
MOST INTERESTING.
WE WERE ATTACKED
BY A THERMONUCLEAR
MISSILE
FROM A PLANET
WHICH SHOULD HAVE
NO SUCH WEAPON.
ORBIT COMPUTED
AND LOCKED IN,
SIR.
EXECUTE.
CAPTAIN, NO RESPONSE
FROM JOHN GILL
ON ANY CHANNEL.
HE MUST BE DEAD.
AND WHAT'S
GOING ON
DOWN THERE
ON EKOS?
ACCORDING
TO OUR RECORDS,
THE EKOSIANS
ARE A PRIMITIVE,
WARLIKE PEOPLE
IN A STATE OF ANARCHY.
THE OTHER PLANET, ZEON,
HAS A RELATIVELY
HIGH TECHNOLOGY,
AND ITS PEOPLE
ARE PEACEFUL.
WE'VE RUN INTO A FAR MORE
SERIOUS PROBLEM
THAN THE DISAPPEARANCE
OF JOHN GILL.
SPOCK, YOU AND I
WILL BEAM DOWN.
BONES, ONE PRECAUTION--
PREPARE A SUBCUTANEOUS
TRANSPONDER
IN THE EVENT WE CAN'T
USE OUR COMMUNICATORS.
INSERT THE TRANSPONDER,
DOCTOR.
MAKE ONE LOW PASS
TO COMMUNICATION RANGE
IN THREE HOURS.
IF WE FAIL TO MAKE CONTACT
AT THE APPOINTED TIME,
TAKE OUR COORDINATES
FROM THE TRANSPONDER
AND BEAM US ABOARD,
NO MATTER WHAT
OUR CONDITION MAY BE.
AYE, SIR.
WHATEVER
YOUR CONDITION.
YOU READY?
READY, CAPTAIN.
ENERGIZE.
THE EKOSIANS
ARE HUMANOID,
SO THERE IS APT
TO BE A SIMILARITY
IN ARCHITECTURE.
INTERESTING.
UGH...
HIDE!
THEY'RE RIGHT
BEHIND ME.
HIDE!
ZEON PIG.
ON YOUR FEET, PIG.
CAPTAIN,
THE NONINTERFERENCE
DIRECTIVE.
HOLD HANDS ABOVE
YOUR HEAD, ZEON.
HIGHER.
KEEP YOUR HANDS
IN THE AIR
SO YOU DON'T TOUCH
ANYTHING EKOSIAN.
YOU SWINE HAVE
DEFILED US FOR
THE LAST TIME.
BUT THAT'S NOW ENDED.
MOVE!
UNBELIEVABLE.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE
THOSE UNIFORMS?
MID-20th CENTURY EARTH.
THE NATION STATE
CALLED NAZI GERMANY.
ATTENTION...
AN ANNOUNCEMENT
FROM FUHRER HEADQUARTERS.
TODAY, THE FUHRER
HAS ORDERED OUR
GLORIOUS CAPITAL
TO BE MADE ZEON-FREE.
STARTING AT DAWN, OUR HEROIC
TROOPS BEGAN FLUSHING OUT
THE ZEON MONSTERS
WHO'VE BEEN POISONING
OUR PLANET.
HOW COULD THIS
HAVE HAPPENED?
THE CHANCES
OF ANOTHER PLANET
DEVELOPING A CULTURE
LIKE NAZI GERMANY,
USING THE FORMS,
THE SYMBOLS,
THE UNIFORMS
OF 20th CENTURY EARTH
ARE SO FANTASTICALLY SLIM.
VIRTUALLY
IMPOSSIBLE, CAPTAIN,
YET THE EVIDENCE
IS QUITE CLEAR.
THE FUHRER'S HEADQUARTERS
REPORTS REPULSING AN ATTACK
BY ZEON SPACECRAFT.
OUR MISSILES UTTERLY
DESTROYED THE ENEMY.
YOU LOOK QUITE WELL
FOR A MAN WHO'S BEEN
UTTERLY DESTROYED,
MR. SPOCK.
SIEG HEIL!
AT THIS PATRIOTIC
DEMONSTRATION,
DEPUTY FUHRER MELAKON
PRESENTED THE IRON CROSS,
SECOND CLASS
TO DARAS,
HERO OF THE FATHERLAND.
EVERYWHERE,
PREPARATIONS GO FORWARD
TOWARD THE FINAL DECISION--
DEATH TO ZEON.
LONG LIVE THE FATHERLAND.
LONG LIVE
THE FUHRER.
THAT'S JOHN GILL.
THE FUHRER?
FASCINATING.
YOU, ZEONS!
WHAT KIND OF MONSTERS
ARE THE ZEONS SENDING
AGAINST US?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
HE'S NOT ONE OF US.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN--US?
LOOK AT HIM.
SPOCK,
TAKE HIS UNIFORM.
YOU PROPOSE WE PASS
OURSELVES OFF AS
NAZIS, CAPTAIN?
IF JOHN GILL IS
THE FUHRER,
IT WOULD SEEM
THE LOGICAL APPROACH.
THAT'S VERY WELL
TAKEN, CAPTAIN.
THAT HELMET COVERS
A MULTITUDE OF SINS.
LIEUTENANT,
WHAT HAVE WE HERE?
A ZEON?
YES. OBVIOUSLY HE'S
NOT ONE OF US.
I CAPTURED HIM.
IS THAT NOT THE
CORRECT PROCEDURE
WITH ENEMIES
OF THE FATHERLAND?
WITH ALL ZEON PIGS,
LIEUTENANT.
TAKE CHARGE OF HIM.
WITH PLEASURE.
TODAY WE HAVE A SURPRISE
PLANNED FOR YOU, ZEON.
YOUR UNIFORM,
CAPTAIN.
YES. IT'S A SHAME YOURS
ISN'T AS ATTRACTIVE AS MINE.
GESTAPO, I BELIEVE.
QUITE CORRECT.
YOU SHOULD MAKE
A VERY CONVINCING
NAZI.
LIEUTENANT!
HAVE YOU FORGOTTEN
HOW TO SALUTE?
YOUR PAPERS.
YOUR ORDERS,
LIEUTENANT.
HE WANTS TO SEE YOUR
ORDERS IN THE JACKET.
THE LIEUTENANT'S
A LITTLE DAZED.
HE CAPTURED
SEVERAL ZEONS
SINGLE-HANDED.
ONE OF THE PIGS STRUCK HIM
BEFORE HE DROPPED.
I PROMISE YOU
THAT PIG WILL NEVER
GET UP AGAIN.
GOOD WORK,
LIEUTENANT.
HAIL THE FUHRER.
HAIL TO THE FUHRER.
THIS IS A DAY
TO REMEMBER, MAJOR.
LIEUTENANT?
BETTER SEE A DOCTOR.
YOU DON'T LOOK WELL.
YOUR COLOR.
YES. I SHALL
TEND TO IT, MAJOR.
LIEUTENANT!
YOUR HELMET.
REMOVE IT.
WE HAVE URGENT BUSINESS
WITH THE FUHRER.
LIEUTENANT,
REMOVE YOUR HELMET.
ENOUGH.
DO YOU WISH
TO SPEAK NOW?
TELL ME YOUR ORDERS!
YOU WERE SENT HERE
TO KILL OUR FUHRER.
CONFESS!
DO YOU WANT SOME
MORE PERSUASION?
YOU'RE MAKING THIS
A RATHER ONE-SIDED
CONVERSATION, MAJOR.
DO NOT JOKE WITH ME,
ZEON PIG.
WHO IS THIS ALIEN?
THINGS MIGHT
GO EASIER FOR YOU
IF YOU TELL ME
ABOUT HIM.
LET ME SPEAK TO
YOUR FUHRER.
I'LL TELL HIM EVERYTHING
HE WANTS TO KNOW.
YOU'LL BE GLAD TO
TALK TO ME
BEFORE I'M
THROUGH WITH YOU.
MAJOR.
AH, CHAIRMAN ENEG.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
I AM HONORED.
I'VE BEEN
INTERROGATING
THESE TWO SPIES,
CAPTURED IN--
I'VE HAD A FULL REPORT.
YOU ARE NOT
FROM ZEON.
OBVIOUSLY.
WHERE DO YOU
COME FROM?
I'LL EXPLAIN WHEN
I SEE THE FUHRER.
WHAT IS YOUR BUSINESS
WITH THE FUHRER?
I'LL DISCUSS THAT
ONLY WITH HIM.
PIG!
YOU ARE SPEAKING
TO THE CHAIRMAN
OF THE PARTY.
THAT'S ENOUGH,
MAJOR.
WHAT WERE
THE WEAPONS
FOUND ON YOU?
WHAT DESIGN?
OUR FAMOUS S.S. LABORATORIES
HAVE BEEN UNABLE TO DISCOVER
HOW THE WEAPONS WORK.
EXCELLENCY, GIVE ME
A FEW MINUTES WITH THEM.
I PROMISE YOU, I'LL--
YOU HAD
A FEW MINUTES,
WITHOUT RESULT.
THE TROUBLE
WITH YOU S.S.
IS THAT YOU
DON'T REALIZE
THAT PUNISHMENT
BECOMES INEFFECTIVE
AFTER A CERTAIN POINT.
MEN BECOME...
INSENSITIVE.
YES, EXCELLENCY.
LOCK THEM UP.
LET THEIR PAIN
ARGUE WITH THEM.
THEN I WILL
QUESTION THEM.
EXCELLENCY,
THE STANDING ORDER
IS TO INTERROGATE
AND EXECUTE.
THE INTERROGATION
IS FINISHED,
THEREFORE--
FINISHED?
WHAT HAVE YOU
LEARNED?
HOLD THEM
FOR AN HOUR.
EXCELLENCY,
THE ORDER--
THAT IS
MY ORDER, MAJOR.
I SUGGEST YOU DO NOT
DISOBEY IT.
YES, EXCELLENCY.
ALL RIGHT, PIGS...
I SHALL KEEP MY EYE
ON THE CLOCK.
WHEN THE HOUR IS UP,
YOU WILL DIE
MOST UNPLEASANTLY,
I PROMISE YOU!
LOCK THEM UP.
JOHN GILL
WAS THE KINDEST...
GENTLEST MAN
I EVER KNEW.
FOR HIM
TO BE A NAZI--
AH--
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WHY DID THEY TAKE YOU?
YOU'RE NOT A ZEON.
HE CERTAINLY IS NOT ONE.
WHY DO THE NAZIS
TREAT YOU AS ENEMIES?
HATE ZEONS?
WHY?
BECAUSE WITHOUT US
TO HATE,
THERE WOULD BE NOTHING
TO HOLD THEM TOGETHER.
SO THE PARTY HAS BUILT US
INTO A THREAT,
A DISEASE TO BE WIPED OUT.
IS ZEON
A THREAT TO THEM?
WHERE DID YOU COME FROM?
OUR WARLIKE PERIOD ENDED
DOZENS OF GENERATIONS AGO.
WE CAME HERE,
WE THOUGHT WE WERE
CIVILIZING THE EKOSIANS.
IT WOULD SEEM
THE ASSUMPTION
WAS PREMATURE.
WERE THEY LIKE THIS
WHEN YOU FIRST CAME HERE?
WARLIKE, YES,
BUT NOT VICIOUS.
THAT STARTED
WHEN THE NAZI
MOVEMENT BEGAN.
IT WAS ONLY
A FEW YEARS AGO.
THAT WOULD COINCIDE
WITH THE TIME OF
JOHN GILL'S ARRIVAL.
WHEN THEY'VE
DESTROYED US HERE,
THEY WILL ATTACK
OUR PLANET.
THEY'LL USE
THE TECHNOLOGY
WE GAVE THEM.
THE DANGER IS
THAT TAKING LIFE IS SO
REPUGNANT TO OUR PEOPLE,
I'M AFRAID WE'LL GO DOWN
WITHOUT A STRUGGLE.
BUT AFTER WHAT I SAW
IN THE STREET TODAY,
I THINK I COULD KILL.
DO YOU KNOW THE PLAN
OF THIS BUILDING?
WHY?
IF WE CAN GET TO
THE S.S. WEAPONS LABORATORY--
GET OUR WEAPONS BACK--
WE MIGHT BE ABLE TO
STOP THE SLAUGHTER
OF THE ZEONS.
WHY SHOULD YOU BE INTERESTED
IN SAVING ZEONS?
WE MUST GET
OUR COMMUNICATORS,
CONTACT THE SHIP.
I POINT OUT,
CAPTAIN,
THE FLAW IN THE PLAN
IS THIS LOCKED DOOR
AND THE GUARD
BEYOND IT.
TO THE LOGICAL MIND,
THE OUTLOOK IS
SOMEWHAT GLOOMY.
THE TRANSPONDERS.
YES.
AND A WAY TO SHED
SOME LIGHT ON
THE GLOOM, MR. SPOCK.
OF COURSE.
THE RUBINDIUM CRYSTALS
IN THE TRANSPONDERS.
ARE--ARE YOU TRYING
TO KILL YOURSELVES?
I KNOW IT'S THERE.
McCOY PUT IT IN.
THERE.
DO YOU HAVE THE FIGURES
COMPUTED, MR. SPOCK?
YES. IT WILL BE
NECESSARY TO HOLD
THE CRYSTALS
RIGIDLY AT
A SPECIFIC DISTANCE,
WHICH I BELIEVE
SHOULD BE 27.2
MILLIMETERS.
27.2 MILLIMETERS
WOULD BE
APPROXIMATELY...
THERE.
THAT IS, OF COURSE,
A CRUDE ESTIMATION.
OF COURSE.
WHAT IS IT YOU'RE
MAKING THERE,
SOME KIND OF RADIO?
NO, NOT A RADIO.
THE POWER FROM THIS
LIGHT IS VERY LOW.
YES. TO REACH THAT
LIGHT,
I SHALL REQUIRE SOME
SORT OF PLATFORM.
I WOULD BE HONORED,
MR. SPOCK.
NOW, THE RUBINDIUM
CRYSTALS SHOULD FIND
ENOUGH POWER HERE
TO ACHIEVE
THE NECESSARY
STIMULUS.
AS I RECALL
FROM THE HISTORY
OF PHYSICS,
THE ANCIENT LASERS
WERE ABLE TO ACHIEVE
THE NECESSARY
EXCITATION,
EVEN USING CRUDE
NATURAL CRYSTALS.
OHH--MR. SPOCK,
THE GUARD DID
A VERY PROFESSIONAL
JOB ON MY BACK.
I'D APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU'D HURRY.
YES, OF COURSE,
CAPTAIN.
YOU REALIZE THAT
THE AIM
WILL, OF COURSE,
BE VERY CRUDE.
I...
DON'T CARE IF YOU
HIT THE BROAD SIDE
OF A BARN.
JUST HURRY, PLEASE.
CAPTAIN,
WHY SHOULD I AIM
AT SUCH A STRUCTURE?
NEVER MIND, SPOCK.
JUST GET ON
WITH THE JOB.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
BEAUTIFUL.
OH, SPOCK...
SPOCK...
BEAUTIFUL.
OVER THERE.
I'LL CREATE A COMMOTION.
HELP!
HELP! I'LL TALK!
I'LL TALK!
I CAN'T STAND IT ANYMORE!
GUARD!
GUARD, I'LL TALK!
[DOOR OPENS]
GUARD, I'LL TALK.
I'LL TALK.
THE PAIN...
TAKE ME WITH YOU.
GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO FIGHT THEM.
CAPTAIN, I
REMIND YOU,
WE DID NOT
INTEND TO FIGHT.
TAKE ME WITH YOU,
OR YOU'LL NEVER FIND
THE LABORATORY.
TAKE HIM WITH US,
MR. SPOCK.
HE'S GOT A POINT.
HE'S OUR GUIDE.
WHICH IS
THE LABORATORY DOOR?
THE END OF THE HALL.
[DOOR CLOSES]
ALL RIGHT,
ZEON PIGS, MOVE.
OHH.
ZEON PIG.
THEY DO
NOTHING RIGHT.
DON'T WORRY.
THEY'RE
ON THEIR WAY
TO THE LABORATORY
FOR EXPERIMENTAL
WORK.
THEY'LL PAY.
MOVE!
MOVE! MOVE!
COVER THE DOOR.
HERE THEY ARE--
THE COMMUNICATORS...
DISASSEMBLED.
CAN YOU
GET ONE TO WORK?
POSSIBLY.
WHO ARE YOU PEOPLE?
THE PHASERS?
I DO NOT SEE THEM.
WHERE DO YOU COME FROM?
THE ALIEN PISTOLS
HAVE BEEN SENT
TO GESTAPO COMMAND
HEADQUARTERS.
WELL, THAT TAKES CARE
OF THE PHASERS.
YOU ZEONS,
FOR PEACEFUL PEOPLE,
ARE PRETTY THOROUGH.
YES.
WITH THIS UNIFORM,
WE CAN STEAL A CAR,
GET OUT OF THE CAPITAL.
WE CAME TO GET
JOHN GILL.
CAPTAIN,
WITHOUT PHASERS,
AND UNTIL WE'RE ABLE TO
COMMUNICATE WITH THE SHIP,
IT IS ILLOGICAL TO ASSUME
THAT WE CAN HOLD OUT
AGAINST THE ENTIRE
MILITARY FORCE
OF THIS PLANET.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
YOU'VE MADE YOUR POINT.
GET INTO THE UNIFORM
AND HIDE THOSE EARS AGAIN.
HUNTING'S GOOD.
WE'VE CAUGHT SO MANY ZEONS,
WE'VE GOT TO
DUMP THEM OUTSIDE.
WHO'S WITH YOU?
DAVOD, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THEY HELPED ME ESCAPE
FROM THE PRISON.
I OWE THEM MY LIFE.
ISAK, WHAT IS ALL THIS?
ABROM...
ABROM, THANK GOD
YOU'RE WELL.
THIS IS MY BROTHER.
THEY WERE IN THE PRISON,
BEATEN AS I WAS, ABROM.
WHY WERE YOU
IN THEIR PRISON?
I WAS TRYING TO SEE
THE FUHRER.
THE FUHRER?
IF I CAN SEE HIM,
THERE MAY BE A WAY OF
STOPPING THIS INSANITY.
ABROM,
I OWE THEM MY LIFE.
ISAK...
ULETTA...
IS DEAD...
SHOT DOWN
IN THE STREETS.
SH-SHE WOULD'VE
BEEN MY WIFE.
SHE LIVED FOR FIVE HOURS...
WHILE THEY
WALKED PAST HER...
AND SPAT ON HER.
OUR OWN PEOPLE WERE
UNABLE TO HELP HER.
NOW YOU ASK ME TO...
HELP STRANGERS.
IF WE ADOPT
THE WAYS OF THE NAZIS,
WE'RE AS BAD AS THE NAZIS.
CAPTAIN...
I SUGGEST
THE MOST PROFITABLE
USE OF OUR TIME
WOULD BE
TO REASSEMBLE
OUR COMMUNICATORS.
MAY I WORK
UNDISTURBED
SOMEWHERE?
THIS WAY.
BY USING PARTS
FROM BOTH,
I'VE COMPLETED
ONE COMMUNICATOR.
I DO NOT KNOW
IF THE CIRCUITS
ARE CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO TEST IT,
EXCEPT IN ACTUAL USE.
THE ENTERPRISE
WON'T BE WITHIN RANGE
FOR ANOTHER HOUR.
OVER THERE
AGAINST THE WALL,
ALL OF YOU.
THE GIRL ON THE
VIEWSCREEN, CAPTAIN--
THE ONE RECEIVING A MEDAL.
DARAS.
QUIET.
HANDS IN THE AIR,
ZEON SWINE.
SO YOU'RE THE THREE
WHO ESCAPED FROM
THE CHANCELLERY
DETENTION CENTER.
WHAT WAS YOUR PLAN? SPEAK.
IT'S THE LAST CHANCE
YOU'LL GET.
I MUST SEE
THE FUHRER.
IT'S URGENT.
URGENT?
I'LL BET IT IS.
I ALONE AM
RESPONSIBLE FOR
WHAT HAPPENS HERE.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT WE DO
TO RESPONSIBLE ZEONS?
NOW WE FINISH THE JOB.
STOP, NAZIS.
AFTER YOU'VE KILLED
THE LAST OF US OFF,
WHAT DO YOU DO,
TURN THE GUNS AGAINST
YOURSELVES?
NO, DON'T SHOOT.
DON'T SHOOT,
PLEASE.
NO, WAIT.
NO MORE.
YOU'VE PROVED
THEY'RE
ON OUR SIDE.
NOW, PLEASE FORGIVE US,
BUT WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN.
YES. IF WE
HAD TAKEN YOU
INTO OUR CONFIDENCE,
WE COULD'VE BETRAYED
ALL OUR PEOPLE,
IF YOU HAD
BEEN NAZI SPIES.
ALL RIGHT, LEAVE US.
THE GESTAPO METHODS
ARE FRIGHTENINGLY EFFICIENT.
WE MUST BE VERY,
VERY CAREFUL
IN ORDER TO SURVIVE HERE.
WE OF THE UNDERGROUND
DON'T KNOW
WHO OUR LEADERS ARE.
THAT WAY, IF WE BREAK
UNDER PRESSURE,
WE CAN ONLY BETRAY
A HANDFUL OF OUR PEOPLE.
THIS YOUNG LADY'S
A NAZI,
A HERO
OF THE FATHERLAND.
WE SAW HER
BEING DECORATED.
I'M AN EKOSIAN,
FIGHTING
THE TERRIBLE THING
THAT'S HAPPENED
TO MY PEOPLE.
THE DECORATION
WAS FOR BETRAYING
MY OWN FATHER
TO THE PARTY.
IT WAS
MY FATHER'S IDEA.
SEE, HE USED TO BE
VERY CLOSE
TO THE FUHRER.
THEN HE
SAW THE CHANGES
AND WHERE
THEY WERE LEADING.
HE TURNED
AGAINST THE PARTY.
THEY IMPRISONED HIM.
MELAKON SENTENCED
HIM TO DEATH.
MELAKON?
THE DEPUTY FUHRER.
HE'S TAKEN OVER.
MY FATHER
DENOUNCED ME,
MAKING IT APPEAR
AS THOUGH I HAD
BETRAYED HIM.
HE GAVE ME A WEAPON
TO CONTINUE
THE FIGHT WITH.
BUT HOW COULD THIS
HAVE SEEMED RIGHT
TO JOHN GILL?
WHO?
JOHN GILL,
YOUR FUHRER.
HE'S ONE OF OUR PEOPLE.
AND WHAT IS
YOUR PEOPLE?
I'M CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE UNITED
SPACESHIP ENTERPRISE.
THIS IS MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
JOHN GILL,
YOUR FUHRER,
WAS SENT HERE
BY THE FEDERATION
AS A CULTURAL OBSERVER.
YOU MEAN THAT
THE FUHRER IS AN ALIEN?
[SPOCK]
THAT IS CORRECT.
I GREW UP TO ADMIRE HIM,
LATER TO HATE AND DESPISE
EVERYTHING HE STANDS FOR.
BUT I ALWAYS THOUGHT
HE WAS ONE OF US.
NOW TO HEAR HE'S AN ALIEN
SENT HERE TO DESTROY US--
THAT WAS NOT
HIS MISSION, EVER.
HE WAS SENT HERE
TO OBSERVE,
NOT TO INTERFERE.
SOMETHING
WENT WRONG,
AND THAT'S
WHY WE'RE HERE,
TO FIND OUT
AND TO CORRECT.
WE MUST SEE HIM.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
EVEN IF THIS
WERE ANOTHER TIME,
IT STILL WOULD BE
IMPOSSIBLE.
HE SEES NO ONE--
NO ONE BUT MELAKON,
AND HE'S UNDER
MAXIMUM SECURITY.
MAXIMUM SECURITY?
IS HE SO AFRAID?
THERE ARE MANY OF US--
EKOSIANS AND
YOUNGER ZEONS--
WHO WOULD GLADLY
RISK OUR LIVES
TO KILL HIM.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE.
THIS GOES AGAINST
EVERY PRINCIPLE
THAT JOHN GILL
EVER BELIEVED IN.
OUR ONLY CHANCE
IS TO SEE HIM,
AND QUICKLY.
HE MAKES A SPEECH TONIGHT
FROM THE CHANCELLERY.
ALL THE TOP PARTY OFFICIALS
WILL BE THERE.
WILL YOU BE THERE?
OF COURSE,
AS A SYMBOL
OF THE PROPER ATTITUDE
TOWARD THE FATHERLAND.
AS AN HONORED MEMBER
OF THE PARTY,
SHE COULD GET US
PAST THE GUARDS.
ONLY THE TOP,
MOST TRUSTED OFFICIALS
WILL BE ALLOWED IN.
THE COUNTRY WILL WATCH
FROM THE VIEWSCREENS.
NO ONE KNOWS
FOR SURE, BUT I'M
AFRAID IT WILL BE
A FORMAL DECLARATION
OF WAR AGAINST ZEON,
THEIR FINAL SOLUTION.
YOU MUST GET US
IN THERE.
IT WOULD BE SUICIDE.
THERE'S A RISK LIVING
AT ALL, THE WAY THINGS
ARE GOING.
IF THE CAPTAIN BELIEVES
HE HAS A CHANCE,
I'M WILLING
TO COMMIT SUICIDE
WITH HIM.
YOU, A ZEON?
YOU EXPECT TO GET
INTO THE CHANCELLERY?
IT'S EVEN MORE MY FIGHT
THAN YOURS.
LIGHTS.
YOU. WHAT IS
YOUR BUSINESS
HERE?
GET ME SOME LIGHTS
ON HER.
IT'S PARTY SECRETARY
DARAS.
THE FUHRER'S
SPECIAL DOCUMENTARY CORPS.
SMILE, CORPORAL.
EXCUSE ME.
CAPTAIN, I'M BEGINNING
TO UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU EARTHMEN
ENJOY GAMBLING.
NO MATTER HOW CAREFULLY
ONE COMPUTES THE ODDS
OF SUCCESS,
THERE IS STILL
A CERTAIN EXHILARATION
IN THE RISK.
VERY GOOD, SPOCK.
WE MAY MAKE A HUMAN
OF YOU YET.
I HOPE NOT.
LET'S GO.
LIGHTS.
THANK YOU.
WHERE DOES
THE FUHRER ENTER?
HE DOESN'T.
THEY WATCH HIM
ON THE BIG SCREEN...
THERE,
AT THE END
OF THE ROOM.
HE BROADCASTS
FROM THE BOOTH
FOR SECURITY.
HMM.
THEY'VE GOT THE
BOOTH CURTAINED OFF.
BRING THAT LIGHT TO
THE SIDE OF HER FACE.
WHERE'S THE ENTRANCE
TO THE BROADCAST BOOTH?
THERE,
AT THE END
OF THE CORRIDOR.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
TRY TO GET INTO
THE BROADCAST BOOTH.
WE'RE GOING TO TRY.
THIS LIGHT COULD BE
A LITTLE HIGHER.
GOOD.
IF YOU'LL DISTRACT
THE GUARD LONG ENOUGH,
I CAN GET A MACHINE GUN.
IT'S A SMALL BOOTH.
I CAN SHOOT THROUGH
THE DOOR.
WE'RE HERE TO GET
JOHN GILL--
AND ALIVE,
NOT FOR YOUR
PERSONAL
SATISFACTION.
IS THAT CLEAR?
LET'S TRY
DOWN THERE.
LIGHTS, PLEASE.
GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS FOR THE RECORD
OF THE FUHRER'S
FINAL SOLUTION SPEECH.
[DARAS]
WE'RE DOCUMENTING
THE MEN RESPONSIBLE FOR...
SMILE, GENTLEMEN.
THERE WILL BE
MORE COVERAGE LATER.
THANK YOU.
LET'S GET A MOVING SHOT
DOWN THE HALL.
SO, WHAT HAVE
WE ACCOMPLISHED?
YOU SHOULD HAVE
LET ME SHOOT THEM.
CAPTAIN,
IT WAS JOHN GILL,
BUT HE NEVER MOVED,
NEVER ONCE LOOKED UP.
YES. THAT MAY
BE PART OF THE PLAN,
THE SEMIDIVINE DETACHMENT.
OR A DEEP PSYCHOSIS.
IT MAY BE
SIMPLER THAN THAT.
HE MAY BE DRUGGED.
WE NEED McCOY.
IS THERE A PLACE--
A ROOM WE CAN BE ALONE
FOR A FEW MINUTES?
I'M GOING TO SEND
FOR HELP.
SEND FOR--
THIS TAKES TOO LONG
TO EXPLAIN.
ANY PLACE WILL DO.
THE CLOAKROOM?
IT MAY NOT HAVE
THE RANGE IT HAD.
IN FACT, IT MAY NOT
WORK AT ALL.
THINK POSITIVELY,
SPOCK.
[STATIC]
SPOCK
TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN,
ENTERPRISE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
CAPTAIN HERE.
PUT McCOY ON.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE NOT
READING YOU WELL.
YOU'RE NINE POINTS INTO
THE LOW-FREQUENCY BAND.
WE'VE HAVING DIFFICULTY.
PATCH HISTORICAL COMPUTER
INTO UNIFORM SECTION.
I WANT McCOY OUTFITTED
AS A GESTAPO DOCTOR--
NAZI GERMANY,
OLD EARTH DATE 1944.
MAKE HIM A COLONEL.
YES, SIR.
SEARCH THE BUILDING.
[McCOY]
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT, JIM?
WE FOUND JOHN GILL.
AT LEAST, WE'VE SEEN HIM.
HE MAY BE DRUGGED,
HYPNOTIZED, OR PSYCHOTIC.
YOU'LL HAVE TO MAKE
A DETERMINATION.
HURRY WITH THAT UNIFORM.
WHAT IS IT?
ISAK JUST HEARD
TWO SECURITY MEN.
THEY PICKED UP
YOUR BROADCAST,
PINPOINTED IT
WITHIN THIS BUILDING.
THEY'RE STARTING
TO SEARCH.
IF THERE'S GOING TO
BE A DELAY
IN TRANSPORTING
THE DOCTOR,
I SUGGEST
WE CANCEL--
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING UP THERE?
DR. McCOY IS
HAVING DIFFICULTY
WITH THAT UNIFORM, SIR.
SEND HIM DOWN NAKED
IF YOU HAVE TO.
KIRK OUT.
IT'S TRUE.
I ONLY HALF-BELIEVED
WHAT YOU SAID.
STUPID COMPUTER
MADE A MISTAKE
IN THE MEASUREMENTS.
THE RIGHT BOOT'S
TOO TIGHT.
THERE IS A LOGICAL
WAY TO PROCEED, DOCTOR.
YOU POINT YOUR TOE,
APPLY EQUAL PRESSURE
TO EITHER SIDE
OF THE BOOT, AND PUSH.
WE HAVE NO TIME
FOR EMOTIONALISM.
THIS
IS DR. McCOY,
OUR CHIEF
MEDICAL OFFICER.
DARAS, SECRETARY
TO THE NATIONAL
SOCIALIST PARTY.
HOW DO YOU DO?
WHAT IN BLAZES IS THIS?
[DOOR OPENS]
CHAIRMAN ENEG.
UH...
THE COLONEL
IS DRUNK.
HE'S HAD
A LITTLE TOO
MUCH TO DRINK.
I SEE.
YES. HE THOUGHT
HE WOULD EMBARRASS
THE FUHRER.
YES. A DOCTOR
SHOULD HAVE MORE PRIDE.
YOU WERE RIGHT
TO CONCEAL HIM.
THERE'S A SPY
IN THIS BUILDING
WITH A SECRET TRANSMITTER.
WE'RE CONDUCTING A SEARCH.
HAIL THE FUHRER.
HAIL FUHRER.
CAPTAIN, I DO NOT
UNDERSTAND HOW HE FAILED
TO RECOGNIZE US.
NOR DO I,
BUT LUCK
IS SOMETHING
YOU ALSO FAIL
TO RECOGNIZE,
MR. SPOCK.
TRUE.
I SHALL RECONSIDER.
[BUZZER]
FUHRER'S SPEECH.
LET'S GO.
HAIL FUHRER!
EKOSIANS...
THE JOB AHEAD
IS DIFFICULT.
IT REQUIRES COURAGE
AND DEDICATION.
IT REQUIRES FAITH.
[APPLAUSE]
THE ZEON COLONY
HAS EXISTED FOR NEARLY...
WATCH HIS MOUTH.
IF WE FULFILL
OUR OWN GREATNESS,
THAT WILL ALL BE ENDED.
WORKING TOGETHER...
CAPTAIN,
THE SPEECH FOLLOWS
NO LOGICAL PATTERN.
RANDOM SENTENCES
STRUNG TOGETHER.
HE LOOKS
DRUGGED, JIM,
ALMOST
IN A CATALEPTIC
STATE.
REACH OUR GOAL,
AND WE WILL
REACH THAT GOAL.
YAY!
I'VE GOT TO HAVE
A CLOSE LOOK
AT HIM.
MUST BE DECISIVE.
EVERY THOUGHT
DIRECTED TOWARD A GOAL.
THIS PLANET
CAN BECOME A PARADISE
IF WE ARE WILLING
TO PAY THE PRICE.
AS EACH CELL IN THE BODY
WORKS WITH DISCIPLINE
AND HARMONY FOR THE GOOD
OF THE ENTIRE
BEING...
GENTLEMEN, I WANT
A PICTURE OF YOU TWO
WITH THE HERO OF
THE FATHERLAND
LISTENING TO THE
STIRRING FUHRER'S SPEECH.
GET THAT LIGHT
OVER THERE, PLEASE.
GET THIS LIGHT
AROUND HERE.
SMILE, GENTLEMEN.
TURN AROUND,
SMILE, AND--NOW.
HAIL FUHRER!
THE FUHRER
HAS GIVEN US OUR ORDERS,
AND WE PLEDGE HIM OUR LIVES
IN THIS SACRED TASK.
DEATH TO ZEON!
DEFINITELY DRUGGED,
ALMOST COMATOSE.
WHAT DRUG?
I CAN'T IDENTIFY IT
WITHOUT A MEDI-COMP.
WITHOUT KNOWING,
AN ANTIDOTE
WOULD BE DANGEROUS.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN DO?
I CAN GIVE HIM
A GENERAL STIMULANT,
BUT IT WOULD BE RISKY.
TAKE THE RISK.
[MELAKON]
DESPITE OUR BEST EFFORTS,
THEY REMAIN,
LIKE A CANCER,
EATING AWAY AT OUR STATE.
YAY!
THERE'S NO REACTION.
WHATEVER YOU GAVE HIM
ISN'T WORKING.
BONES...
INCREASE THE DOSAGE.
I'M WORKING IN THE DARK.
I COULD KILL HIM.
IF THEY FIND US HERE,
WE'LL ALL BE KILLED.
10 MINUTES AGO,
ON OUR FUHRER'S ORDERS,
OUR TROOPS BEGAN
THEIR HISTORIC MISSION.
IN THE CITIES,
THE ELIMINATIONS
HAVE STARTED.
WITHIN AN HOUR,
THE ZEON BLIGHT WILL FOREVER
BE REMOVED FROM EKOS.
IT'S BEGUN.
IT'S FINALLY BEGUN.
THE STIMULANT'S
WORKING.
I NOW ANNOUNCE...
HE'S REACHING A LEVEL
OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
HE'S IN A LIGHT SLEEP.
NOW, THAT'S AS MUCH
AS I DARE DO.
OUR ENTIRE SOLAR SYSTEM
WILL FOREVER BE RID
OF THE DISEASE
THAT WAS ZEON.
SPOCK...
TRY TO GET
THROUGH TO HIM
WITH THE MIND PROBE.
IF YOU CAN'T, BONES,
YOU'LL HAVE TO USE
A STRONGER STIMULANT,
NO MATTER WHAT IT DOES.
OUR SPACE FLEET
IS ON ITS WAY TOWARD ZEON,
BOTH MANNED
AND UNMANNED WEAPONS.
THIS IS THE TIME
OF DESTINY.
HAIL VICTORY!
THERE'S
ONE CHANCE LEFT.
IF YOU'D USE
THE WEAPONS
YOU HAVE,
YOU
COULD DESTROY
THE FLEET.
THAT WOULD MEAN
THE DEATH OF THOUSANDS
OF EKOSIAN SPACE MEN.
I KNOW.
MANY OF MY FRIENDS
ARE ABOARD THAT SHIP,
MANY OF THE UNDERGROUND.
YES, BUT AGAINST
THOSE THOUSANDS
ARE MILLIONS
UPON MILLIONS
OF INNOCENT
ZEON LIVES.
YOU'VE
GOT TO CHOOSE
THE LESSER
OF TWO EVILS.
WE COULD SAVE ZEON...
BUT WHAT ABOUT EKOS?
CAPTAIN.
I'VE CREATED
A CONDITION
IN WHICH GILL
CANNOT INITIATE SPEECH
OR ANY OTHER ACTION,
BUT HE CAN REPLY
TO QUESTIONS.
WELL DONE, SPOCK.
THEY'VE KEPT
WHAT'S LEFT OF HIM
AS A FIGUREHEAD.
QUITE CORRECT.
FOR THE LAST FEW YEARS,
THE REAL POWER
HAS BEEN MELAKON.
GILL.
GILL, WHY DID YOU
ABANDON YOUR MISSION?
WHY DID YOU INTERFERE
WITH THIS CULTURE?
PLANET...
FRAGMENTED...
DIVIDED.
TOOK LESSON
FROM EARTH HISTORY.
BUT WHY NAZI GERMANY?
YOU STUDIED HISTORY.
YOU KNEW WHAT THE NAZIS WERE.
MOST EFFICIENT
STATE...
EARTH EVER KNEW.
QUITE TRUE, CAPTAIN.
THAT TINY COUNTRY--
BEATEN, BANKRUPT,
DEFEATED,
ROSE IN A FEW YEARS
TO STAND
ONLY ONE STEP AWAY
FROM GLOBAL DOMINATION.
BUT IT WAS BRUTAL,
PERVERTED,
HAD TO BE DESTROYED
AT A TERRIBLE COST.
WHY THAT EXAMPLE?
PERHAPS GILL FELT
THAT SUCH A STATE,
RUN BENIGNLY,
COULD ACCOMPLISH
ITS EFFICIENCY
WITHOUT SADISM.
WHY, GILL?
WHY?
WORKED.
AT FIRST...
IT WORKED.
THEN MELAKON...
BEGAN TO TAKE OVER.
USED THE...
GAVE ME THE DRUG.
GILL.
GILL, CAN YOU
HEAR ME?
YOU'VE GOT TO TELL
THOSE PEOPLE WHAT HAPPENED!
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE WHO
CAN PREVENT THE SLAUGHTER!
GILL!
HE'S STILL ALIVE,
BUT THE DRUG
THEY USE IS TOO STRONG.
IF I GIVE HIM
ANOTHER SHOT, WE'RE--
BONES, GIVE HIM
ANOTHER SHOT!
I DON'T DARE.
GUARD.
WE'VE RUN OUT
OF TIME, BONES.
NOW, WAIT.
AIM IT AT SPOCK.
SPOCK, TAKE OFF THE HELMET.
THE SECOND TIME
IN ONE DAY,
DARAS IS A HERO
TO THE FATHERLAND.
SHE CAPTURED
A ZEON SPY
THAT WAS ATTEMPTING
TO ASSASSINATE
THE FUHRER.
GUARDS.
YES, LET US
MAKE AN EXAMPLE
OF THIS TRAITOR
ONCE AND FOR ALL.
WE'LL MAKE A PRESENT
OF HIM TO MELAKON.
CHAIRMAN ENEG,
THIS SPY MUST BE TAKEN
TO MELAKON.
PASS THEM
ON MY RESPONSIBILITY.
ENEG IS ONE OF US.
STAY CLOSE TO SPOCK.
STALL FOR TIME.
AND HOPE.
WHAT IS THIS?
A SPY, EXCELLENCY.
A RARE PRIZE.
THE DEPUTY FUHRER
CAN SEE
THIS IS
NO ORDINARY ZEON.
NOT A ZEON,
DEFINITELY NOT.
PROFESSOR GILL...
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
YOU'VE GOT TO SPEAK.
THIS IS OUR LAST CHANCE.
GILL.
THE DEPUTY FUHRER
IS AN AUTHORITY
ON THE GENETICS
OF RACIAL PURITY.
HOW WOULD YOU
CLASSIFY THIS ONE?
VERY DIFFICULT.
NOTE
THE SINISTER EYES
AND THE MALFORMED
EARS.
DEFINITELY
AN INFERIOR RACE.
[SLAP]
PROFESSOR...
PROFESSOR,
YOU'VE GOT TO TALK.
YOU'VE GOT TO TELL THEM
WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU'VE GOT TO COME
OUT OF IT.
COME ON, PROFESSOR.
COME ON.
NOTE
THE LOW FOREHEAD,
DENOTING STUPIDITY,
THE DULL LOOK
OF A TRAPPED ANIMAL.
YOU MAY TAKE HIM NOW
FOR INTERROGATION,
BUT I WANT
THE BODY SAVED FOR
THE CULTURAL MUSEUM.
HE'LL MAKE
AN INTERESTING
DISPLAY.
PEOPLE.
PEOPLE OF EKOS...
GO TO THE BOOTH.
SEE TO
THE FUHRER
AT ONCE.
HE'S ILL.
TURN OFF
THAT CAMERA.
HEAR ME.
I SUGGEST WE LEAVE
AND LET
OUR FUHRER REST.
WE WERE BETRAYED
BY A SELF-SEEKING
ADVENTURER...
WHO HAS LED US ALL
TO THE VERY BRINK
OF DISASTER.
[DOORKNOB TURNS]
I ORDER THE IMMEDIATE RECALL
OF THE SPACE FLEET.
THIS ATTACK...
MUST STOP.
ALL UNITS
ARE TO RETURN TO BASE.
TO ZEON, I PROMISE,
THIS WAS NOT
AN AGGRESSION
OF THE EKOSIAN PEOPLE...
ONLY ONE EVIL MAN.
MELAKON IS A TRAITOR
TO HIS OWN PEOPLE
AND ALL
THAT WE STAND FOR.
THE ZEON PEOPLE...
I PROMISE REPARATION
AND...
WAIT, SOLDIER.
THERE'S BEEN
ENOUGH KILLING.
NOW WE'LL
START TO LIVE
THE WAY THE FUHRER
MEANT US TO LIVE.
I WAS WRONG.
THE NONINTERFERENCE
DIRECTIVE...
IS THE ONLY WAY.
WE MUST STOP
THE SLAUGHTER.
YOU DID THAT,
PROFESSOR.
YOU TOLD THEM
IN TIME.
EVEN HISTORIANS...
FAIL TO LEARN
FROM HISTORY.
THEY REPEAT
THE SAME MISTAKES.
LET THE KILLING END.
LET...
[KNOCK KNOCK]
IS HE DEAD,
CAPTAIN?
DEAD.
FOR SO LONG,
I'VE PRAYED FOR THIS.
NOW I'M SORRY.
SO IS HE.
YOU'VE GIVEN
US ALL A NEW CHANCE.
THANK YOU,
BUT GO NOW.
WE MUST DO THE REST.
ENEG AND I WILL
GO ON THE AIR,
OFFER A NEW WAY
FOR OUR PEOPLE,
FOR
ALL OUR PEOPLE,
BOTH ZEONS
AND EKOSIANS.
IT IS TIME TO STOP
THE BLOODSHED,
TO BURY OUR DEAD.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
I THINK THE PLANET
IS IN GOOD HANDS.
INDEED, CAPTAIN.
WITH THE UNION
OF TWO CULTURES,
THIS SYSTEM WOULD MAKE
A FINE ADDITION
TO THE FEDERATION.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
[UHURA]
ENTERPRISE HERE, CAPTAIN.
BEAM US ABOARD.
CAPTAIN, I NEVER WILL
UNDERSTAND HUMANS.
HOW COULD A MAN
AS BRILLIANT--
A MIND AS LOGICAL
AS JOHN GILL'S HAVE MADE
SUCH A FATAL ERROR?
HE DREW
THE WRONG CONCLUSION
FROM HISTORY.
THE PROBLEM WITH THE NAZIS
WASN'T SIMPLY
THAT THEIR LEADERS
WERE EVIL, PSYCHOTIC MEN.
THEY WERE,
BUT THE MAIN PROBLEM,
I THINK, WAS
THE LEADER PRINCIPLE.
WHAT HE'S
SAYING, SPOCK,
IS THAT A MAN
WHO HOLDS
THAT MUCH POWER,
EVEN WITH
THE BEST INTENTIONS,
JUST CAN'T
RESIST THE URGE
TO PLAY GOD.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I WAS ABLE TO
GATHER THE MEANING.
IT ALSO PROVES
ANOTHER
EARTH SAYING--
"ABSOLUTE POWER
CORRUPTS
ABSOLUTELY."
DARN CLEVER,
THESE EARTHMEN,
WOULDN'T YOU SAY?
YES.
EARTHMEN LIKE
RAMSES, ALEXANDER,
CAESAR, NAPOLEON,
HITLER, LEE KUAN.
YOUR WHOLE EARTH HISTORY
IS MADE UP OF MEN
SEEKING ABSOLUTE POWER.
SPOCK, YOU
OBVIOUSLY
DON'T--
OBVIOUSLY, DOCTOR,
YOU FAIL TO ACCEPT--
GENTLEMEN, GENTLEMEN,
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
ONE CIVIL WAR.
LET'S NOT START ANOTHER.
MR. CHEKOV,
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT.
WARP FACTOR 2,
AND HURRY.