NO LIFE FORM READINGS,
CAPTAIN.
CONTINUING SCAN.
WELL, SOMEBODY SENT
A DISTRESS CALL.
NO SIGN OF
THE SPACESHIP.
NO SIGN OF DEBRIS.
I AM
GETTING READINGS
ON SMALL
METALLIC OBJECTS,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S POSSIBLE
THE SHIP WAS
DESTROYED IN SPACE
AND THE SURVIVORS
PROCEEDED HERE
IN A SHUTTLE CRAFT.
BUT WHERE ARE THEY?
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING
A READING NOW.
TWO HUMAN FORMS
AT BEARING 300
MARK 7.
CONFIRMED.
I'M CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
WE CAME IN ANSWER
TO YOUR DISTRESS CALL.
IT WAS VERY KIND OF YOU
TO RESPOND SO QUICKLY.
NOW YOU WILL SURRENDER
YOUR SHIP TO ME.
YOU HAVE A VERY STRANGE
SENSE OF HUMOR, MR...
I AM ROJAN OF KELVA.
I AM YOUR COMMANDER
FROM THIS MOMENT ON.
ANY EFFORTS
TO RESIST US...
OR TO ESCAPE...
WILL BE
SEVERELY PUNISHED.
SOON WE...
AND YOU...
WILL LEAVE
THIS GALAXY FOREVER.
YOU HUMANS...
MUST FACE THE END
OF YOUR EXISTENCE
AS YOU HAVE KNOWN IT.
SPACE...
A FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
YOU ARE ALL PARALYZED
BY A SELECTIVE FIELD
THAT NEUTRALIZES
NERVE IMPULSES
TO THE VOLUNTARY MUSCLES.
WE CAN CONTROL YOU
AT WILL.
I WILL NOW RELEASE YOU.
[BEEP]
CAPTAIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
INTERESTING.
A NEURAL FIELD?
YES. RADIATING
FROM A CENTRAL
PROJECTOR.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOUR SHIP,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
IT WILL
SERVE US WELL
IN THE LONG VOYAGE.
VOYAGE? WHERE?
TO YOUR
NEIGHBORING GALAXY,
WHICH YOU CALL
ANDROMEDA.
ANDROMEDA?
WHY?
IT IS OUR HOME.
WHAT BRINGS
YOU HERE?
WITHIN 10 MILLENNIA,
HIGH RADIATION LEVELS
IN OUR GALAXY
WILL MAKE LIFE THERE
IMPOSSIBLE.
SO THE KELVAN EMPIRE
SENT FORTH SHIPS
TO EXPLORE
OTHER GALAXIES,
TO SEARCH FOR ONE
WHICH OUR RACE
COULD CONQUER AND OCCUPY.
WELL, SORRY. THIS GALAXY
IS ALREADY OCCUPIED.
CAPTAIN, YOU THINK
YOU ARE UNCONQUERABLE
AND YOUR SHIP
IMPREGNABLE,
BUT WHILE WE'VE TALKED,
THE CAPTURE
HAS ALREADY BEGUN.
SOMETHING PENETRATING
FROM THE PLANET.
INCREASE POWER
TO SHIELDS.
IT'S DEAD, SIR.
ALL MAJOR POWER DISABLED.
SOUND RED ALERT.
RED ALERT.
ALL PERSONNEL
MAN YOUR
BATTLE STATIONS.
GO TO RED ALERT.
ENGINEERING,
COME IN.
LIFE SUPPORT,
DREA, TOMAR, REPORT.
LIFE SUPPORT CONTROL,
SECURE.
ENGINEERING
IS SECURE.
ROJAN,
HANAR HERE.
REPORT, HANAR.
THE SHIP IS OURS.
WE CONTROL THE BRIDGE,
ENGINEERING,
AND LIFE SUPPORT
SYSTEMS.
PROCEED WITH
YOUR ORDERS.
WHAT'S THE POINT
OF CAPTURING MY SHIP?
EVEN AT MAXIMUM WARP,
THE ENTERPRISE
COULDN'T REACH ANDROMEDA
FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS.
CAPTAIN, WE WILL
MODIFY ITS ENGINES
IN ORDER TO
PRODUCE VELOCITIES
FAR BEYOND THE REACH
OF YOUR SCIENCE.
THE JOURNEY
BETWEEN GALAXIES
WILL TAKE LESS THAN
300 OF YOUR YEARS.
FASCINATING.
INTERGALACTIC TRAVEL
REQUIRING ONLY 300 YEARS?
THAT IS A LEAP
FAR BEYOND ANYTHING
MAN HAS YET ACCOMPLISHED.
YOU MADE A VOYAGE
OF 300 YEARS?
OUR SHIPS WERE OF
MULTIGENERATION DESIGN.
WE WERE BORN IN
THE INTERGALACTIC VOID.
WE SHALL DIE THERE
DURING OUR RETURN JOURNEY.
OUR MISSION
WILL BE COMPLETED
BY A COMMANDER WHO IS
MY DESCENDANT.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR SHIP?
THERE IS
AN ENERGY BARRIER
AT THE RIM
OF YOUR GALAXY.
YES, I KNOW.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
WE MANAGED TO BREAK THROUGH IT
WITH GREAT DIFFICULTY.
OUR SHIP WAS DESTROYED.
WE BARELY MANAGED
TO ESCAPE
IN A LIFE CRAFT.
AND NOW...
WE HAVE THE MEANS
TO BEGIN OUR JOURNEY
BACK TO ANDROMEDA.
WHY USE OUR VESSEL?
WHY NOT
TRANSMIT A MESSAGE
TO YOUR GALAXY?
NO FORM OF TRANSMISSION
CAN PENETRATE THE BARRIER.
ROJAN,
THERE'S NO REASON
TO DO THIS BY FORCE.
LET'S TAKE YOUR PROBLEM
TO THE FEDERATION.
RESEARCH EXPEDITIONS
HAVE CATALOGUED HUNDREDS
OF UNINHABITED PLANETS
IN THIS GALAXY
SUITABLE
FOR COLONIZATION.
WE DO NOT COLONIZE.
WE CONQUER.
WE RULE.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY
FOR US.
IN OTHER WORDS,
THE GALAXY
ISN'T BIG ENOUGH
FOR BOTH OF US.
THE FEDERATION
HAS HANDLED FOREIGN
INVASIONS BEFORE.
CAPTAIN, WE CAN CONTROL
THE FEDERATION
AS EASILY AS WE
CAN CONTROL YOU.
THE FATE OF THE INFERIOR
IN ANY GALAXY.
ALL IS PROCEEDING
ACCORDING TO PLAN, ROJAN.
KELINDA, TAKE THEM
TO THE HOLDING AREA.
WE'LL KEEP YOU
AND YOUR PARTY HERE,
CAPTAIN.
YOUR CREW WILL
UNDOUBTEDLY WISH
TO COOPERATE WITH US
IF THEY UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU ARE HOSTAGES.
Kelinda:
MOVE THERE.
TOMAR HAS EXAMINED
THE SHIP.
THE MODIFICATIONS
ARE UNDERWAY.
SPACE AGAIN, HANAR.
I DO NOT THINK
WE COULD HAVE
KEPT OUR SANITY
LIVING TOO LONG
ON THIS ACCURSED PLANET.
IT IS AN UNDISCIPLINED
ENVIRONMENT.
ONE CANNOT CONTROL IT.
YET THERE ARE
THINGS OF INTEREST.
YES, BUT DISTURBING.
THESE SHELLS IN WHICH
WE'VE ENCASED OURSELVES,
THEY HAVE SUCH
HEIGHTENED SENSES.
TO FEEL...
TO HEAR...
TO SMELL.
HOW DO HUMANS
MANAGE TO EXIST
IN THESE
FRAGILE CASES?
SINCE THE SHIP
WAS DESIGNED
TO SUSTAIN
THESE FORMS,
WE HAVE
LITTLE CHOICE.
AT LEAST WE'LL BE AWAY
FROM ALL OF THIS OPENNESS.
NO, THIS IS TOO STRANGE
FOR US, HANAR.
WE ARE CREATURES
OF OUTER SPACE.
SOON...
WE WILL BE SAFE
IN THE COMFORTING
CLOSENESS OF WALLS.
FASCINATING MATERIAL.
SIMILAR TO DIBERNIUM,
BUT CONSIDERABLY
MORE DENSE.
I DOUBT EVEN
PHASER FIRE
COULD DISTURB
ITS MOLECULAR STRUCTURE.
WE CAN'T BREAK OUT.
THERE MUST BE
ANOTHER WAY.
CAPTAIN,
WHO DO THEY WANT
FROM US?
WHAT KIND
OF PEOPLE ARE THEY?
THAT'S A VERY GOOD
QUESTION.
THEY REGISTERED
AS HUMAN.
NO, DOCTOR.
MORE THAN THAT.
THEY REGISTERED AS PERFECT
HUMAN LIFE FORMS.
I RECALL NOTING
THE READINGS WERE
ALMOST CLASSIC
TEXTBOOK RESPONSES.
MOST CURIOUS.
SPOCK, WHAT
ARE THE ODDS
IN SUCH ABSOLUTE
DUPLICATION OF LIFE FORMS
IN ANOTHER GALAXY?
THE CHANCES
ARE VERY MUCH
AGAINST IT.
CAPTAIN, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER PERFECT
THEY ARE,
THERE DON'T SEEM TO BE
VERY MANY OF THEM.
THEY HAVE
THE PARALYSIS FIELD.
ROJAN MENTIONED
SOMETHING ABOUT A...
CENTRAL PROJECTOR.
YES.
IF WE COULD PUT THAT
OUT OF OPERATION,
WE MIGHT HAVE A CHANCE.
GENTLEMEN, I'M
CONSTRAINED TO POINT OUT
WE DO NOT EVEN KNOW
WHAT THIS PROJECTOR
LOOKS LIKE.
THOSE DEVICES ON THEIR BELTS
MIGHT INDICATE THE SOURCE
OF THE FORCE FIELD.
POSSIBLE.
I WOULD HAVE
TO HAVE ONE
TO EXAMINE.
YOU'LL HAVE ONE, SIR,
IF I HAVE TO RIP
ONE OF THE KELVINS
APART TO GET IT.
YOU'LL
GET YOUR CHANCE,
BUT YOU'LL DO IT
UNDER ORDERS.
YES, SIR.
ON EMINIAR SEVEN,
YOU WERE ABLE
TO TRICK THE GUARD
BY A VULCAN MIND PROBE.
AS I RECALL,
CAPTAIN,
I LED HIM TO BELIEVE
WE HAD ESCAPED.
DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN DO IT AGAIN?
I SHALL ATTEMPT IT.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES, I WILL
BE ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
WE MUST HURRY.
[BEEP]
THIS CANNOT GO
UNPUNISHED.
HANAR.
THAT ONE.
TAKE HIM ASIDE.
KELINDA.
THE FEMALE.
CAPTAIN.
GO.
AS A LEADER,
YOU REALIZE THE IMPORTANCE
OF DISCIPLINE.
I NEED YOU AND
THESE OTHER SPECIALISTS,
BUT THOSE TWO
ARE UNNECESSARY.
I'M RESPONSIBLE.
LET THEM GO.
I THINK WE'RE
SOMEWHAT ALIKE, CAPTAIN.
EACH OF US CARES
LESS FOR HIS OWN SAFETY
THAN FOR THE LIVES
OF HIS COMMAND.
WE FEEL PAIN
WHEN OTHERS SUFFER
FOR OUR MISTAKES.
YOUR PUNISHMENT SHALL BE
TO WATCH THEM DIE.
CAPTAIN...
PROCEED, HANAR.
BRING THEM TO ME.
THIS IS THE ESSENCE
OF WHAT THEY WERE.
THE FLESH AND BRAIN
AND WHAT YOU CALL...
A PERSONALITY,
DISTILLED DOWN
INTO THESE COMPACT SHAPES.
ONCE CRUSHED...
THIS PERSON IS DEAD.
HOWEVER...
THAT ONE CAN BE RESTORED.
HANAR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4657.5.
WORK IS PROCEEDING
ON THE ENTERPRISE
AS MY CREW IS FORCED TO
MAKE THE REQUIRED CHANGES
IN THE SHIP
FOR INTERGALACTIC TRAVEL.
I CAN'T FORGET THE PICTURE
OF YEOMAN THOMPSON
CRUSHED TO
A HANDFUL OF DUST.
SPOCK, ARE YOU SURE
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT?
YES, QUITE
ALL RIGHT,
DOCTOR.
YOU DIDN'T
LOOK VERY WELL
WHEN YOU BROKE
THAT MIND TOUCH.
I DID NOT
BREAK IT, DOCTOR.
I WAS THROWN AWAY
BY SOMETHING I'VE NEVER
EXPERIENCED BEFORE.
WHAT WAS IT?
A SERIES OF BIZARRE
AND EXOTIC IMAGES
BURSTING ON MY MIND
AND CONSCIOUSNESS.
COLORS...
SHAPES...
MATHEMATICAL EQUATIONS
FUSED AND BLURRED.
I'VE BEEN ATTEMPTING
TO ISOLATE THEM,
BUT SO FAR I'VE BEEN ABLE
TO RECALL CLEARLY
ONLY ONE.
IMMENSE BEINGS...
100 LIMBS WHICH
RESEMBLE TENTACLES,
MINDS OF SUCH CONTROL
AND CAPACITY
THAT EACH LIMB
IS CAPABLE OF PERFORMING
A DIFFERENT FUNCTION.
DO YOU MEAN THAT'S WHAT
THE KELVANS REALLY ARE?
UNDOUBTEDLY.
WELL, IF THEY
LOOK THAT WAY
NORMALLY,
WHY DID THEY
ADAPT THEMSELVES
TO OUR BODIES?
PERHAPS PRACTICALITY.
THEY CHOSE
THE ENTERPRISE
AS THE BEST VESSEL
FOR THE TRIP.
IMMENSE BEINGS
WITH 100 TENTACLES
WOULD HAVE DIFFICULTY
WITH THE TURBO LIFT.
WE'VE GOT TO STOP THEM.
WE OUTNUMBER THEM.
THEIR ONLY HOLD ON US
IS THE PARALYSIS FIELD.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
ONE WRONG MOVE,
AND THEY JAM
ALL OUR NEURO CIRCUITS.
JAM.
SPOCK,
IF YOU REVERSE
THE CIRCUITS
ON McCOY'S
NEURO-ANALYZER,
CAN YOU SET UP
A COUNTER FIELD
TO JAM THE
PARALYSIS PROJECTOR?
I'M DUBIOUS OF
THE POSSIBILITIES OF
SUCCESS, CAPTAIN.
THE MEDICAL EQUIPMENT
IS NOT DESIGNED
TO PUT OUT A GREAT DEAL
OF POWER.
THE POLARIZED ELEMENTS
WOULD BURN OUT QUICKLY.
IS THERE A CHANCE
AT ALL?
A SMALL ONE.
WE'LL TAKE IT.
YOU AND BONES
HAVE TO GET TO THE SHIP.
HOW?
YES, HO--
MR. SPOCK...
YOU'RE SICK.
I ASSURE YOU, CAPTAIN,
I'M IN PERFECT HEALTH.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
DR. McCOY'S GIVEN YOU
A THROROUGH EXAMINATION,
AND YOU'RE ILL.
IN FACT, IF YOU DON'T
GET TO THE SICK BAY,
YOU'RE GONNA DIE.
IT'S A GOOD IDEA, JIM,
BUT ANYONE LOOKING AT HIM
CAN TELL HE'S HEALTHY.
VULCANS HAVE THE ABILITY
TO PLACE THEMSELVES
IN A KIND OF TRANCE,
COMPLETE RELAXATION
OF EVERY PART OF
THE MIND AND BODY.
WE FIND IT MORE
RESTFUL TO THE BODY
THAN YOUR
SO-CALLED VACATION.
CAN YOU DO IT NOW
AND COME OUT OF IT
IN THE SICK BAY,
SAY, IN A HALF AN HOUR?
IT WILL TAKE ME
A MOMENT TO PREPARE.
GO AHEAD.
JIM...
HIS HEARTBEAT
REALLY IS SLOW.
HIS PULSE IS
PRACTICALLY NONEXISTENT.
HANAR.
WHAT DO YOU WANT,
HUMAN?
MR. SPOCK IS ILL.
THE DOCTOR THINKS
HE MAY BE DYING.
THIS ILLNESS CAME ON HIM
RATHER SUDDENLY.
IS IT NOT UNUSUAL?
HE'S A VULCAN.
THEY DON'T REACT
LIKE HUMANS.
HE MAY DIE!
IF I CAN GET HIM
UP TO SICK BAY,
THERE'S A CHANCE
HE'LL LIVE.
STAND AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
I WILL HAVE YOU
BEAMED ABOARD.
DO WHAT YOU CAN
WITH HIM, BONES.
DOCTOR, WHAT HAPPENED?
PREPARE 2 CCs
OF STOKALINE.
STOKALINE?
BUT, DOCTOR, THAT--
DON'T ARGUE, NURSE.
JUST GET IT.
THIS MAY BE
THE TURNING POINT.
PREPARE ANOTHER SHOT.
BUT, DOC--
PLEASE, NURSE.
JUST FOLLOW ORDERS,
WILL YOU?
THERE, THAT
SHOULD DO IT.
JUST LET HIM
REST NOW.
YOU SEE,
IT'S A FLARE-UP
OF RIGELIAN KASSABA FEVER.
HE SUFFERED FROM IT
ABOUT 10 YEARS AGO,
AND IT RECURS
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
THERE'S NO DANGER
IF HE GETS MEDICATION
IN TIME.
HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
VERY WELL.
I WILL INFORM ROJAN.
YOU WILL STAY HERE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
WITH ME NOW?
WE WILL BEAM ABOARD
THE VESSEL SHORTLY.
I WISH YOU TO UNDERSTAND
YOUR DUTIES.
MY DUTY IS TO STOP YOU
IN ANY WAY I CAN.
YOU WILL OBEY.
OR YOU'LL KILL
MORE OF MY PEOPLE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I CANNOT BELIEVE
THAT YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND
THE IMPORTANCE
OF MY MISSION.
WE KELVANS HAVE
A CODE OF HONOR.
HARSH, DEMANDING.
IT CALLS FOR MUCH
FROM US...
AND MUCH FROM THOSE
WHOM WE CONQUER.
YOU HAVE BEEN CONQUERED.
I RESPECT YOUR DEVOTION
TO YOUR DUTY,
BUT I CANNOT PERMIT IT
TO INTERFERE WITH MINE.
THESE ARE LOVELY.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
WHAT IS IT YOU CALL THEM?
FLOWERS.
I DON'T KNOW
THE VARIETY.
OUR MEMORY TAPES
TELL US OF SUCH THINGS
ON KELVAN.
CRYSTALS THAT FORM
WITH SUCH RAPIDITY,
THEY SEEM TO GROW.
THEY LOOK LIKE
THIS FRAGILE THING SOMEWHAT.
WE CALL THEM SAHSHEER.
A ROSE BY
ANY OTHER NAME.
CAPTAIN?
A QUOTE FROM
A GREAT HUMAN POET...
SHAKESPEARE.
"THAT WHICH WE
CALL A ROSE
BY ANY OTHER NAME...
WOULD SMELL AS SWEET."
DREA HAS COMPUTED
AND LAID A COURSE
FOR KELVA, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE JUMPED TO WARP 8.
WE'LL GO FASTER YET.
INCREASE SPEED
TO WARP 11.
TO WARP 11, MR. CHEKOV.
ON COURSE AND PROCEEDING
AS PLANNED.
WE WILL APPROACH
THE BARRIER
WITHIN AN HOUR.
VERY WELL.
ROJAN,
I'M GOING TO SICK BAY.
MY FIRST OFFICER'S
TAKEN ILL.
YES, I WAS INFORMED.
YOU MAY GO.
ANYTHING?
I'VE LOCATED
THEIR POWER SOURCE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S INSTALLED
IN ENGINEERING.
WE'RE JUST GOING
TO JAM IT.
I'VE TIED IN ALL
THE LAB COMPUTERS.
THAT'LL GIVE US A BIT
MORE POWER TO PUSH WITH.
THIS IS IT.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO--
WHATEVER WE MUST DO,
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WHY?
THIS MATERIAL
SURROUNDING
THE PROJECTOR
IS THE SAME
AS I DISCOVERED
ON THE PLANET.
READINGS INDICATE
IT IS IMPERVIOUS
TO ANY OF OUR WEAPONS.
WE CANNOT
PENETRATE THE CASING
TO GET TO
THE MACHINE.
THAT'S IT, THEN.
THERE IS ONE OTHER
POSSIBILITY, MR. SCOTT.
THE FINAL DECISION,
OF COURSE,
MUST BE THE CAPTAIN'S,
BUT I BELIEVE
WE MUST HAVE IT
READY FOR HIM.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS PROPELLED
BY MATTER-ANTI-MATTER
REACTORS.
THE BARRIER
WE MUST TRAVERSE
IS NEGATIVE ENERGY.
I SEE WHAT
YOU'RE GETTING AT.
I CAN'T SAY I LIKE IT.
NOR I.
BUT IT MUST BE
MADE AVAILABLE
TO THE CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THE BRIDGE, PLEASE.
WELL?
IMPOSSIBLE, CAPTAIN.
THE POWER SOURCE
IS PROTECTED BY A MATERIAL
WE CANNOT BREACH
EVEN WITH OUR PHASERS.
MR. SCOTT AND I
HAVE PREPARED THE MEANS
FOR THE ONLY LOGICAL
ALTERNATIVE TO US.
WHAT ALTERNATIVE?
THE BARRIER
WE MUST PENETRATE
IS COMPOSED
OF NEGATIVE ENERGY.
I HAVE OPENED
THE CONTROL VALVES
TO THE
MATTER-ANTI-MATTER
NACELLES.
ON YOUR SIGNAL,
I'LL FLOOD THEM
WITH POSITIVE ENERGY.
WHAT?
WHEN WE
ENGAGE THE BARRIER,
THE SHIP WILL EXPLODE.
THE KELVANS WILL
BE STOPPED HERE.
AND SO WILL WE.
ARE YOU MAD?
I CAN'T JUST--
TAKE YOUR PLACES,
GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE APPROACHING
THE BARRIER.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4658.9.
WITH THE ENTERPRISE
UNDER CONTROL OF THE KELVANS,
WE ARE APPROACHING
THE ENERGY BARRIER
AT THE EDGE OF OUR GALAXY.
SPOCK AND SCOTTY
HAVE DEVISED A SUICIDE PLAN
TO STOP THE KELVANS.
THEY HAVE RIGGED THE SHIP
TO EXPLODE
ON MY SIGNAL.
READING, SPOCK.
SENSORS INDICATE
DENSITY NEGATIVE,
RADIATION NEGATIVE,
ENERGY NEGATIVE.
ALL INSTRUMENTS
OFF THE DIAL, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE IN CONTACT
WITH THE BARRIER.
OUTSIDE HULL TEMPERATURES
RISING, SIR.
OVER 2,000 DEGREES NOW.
SIR!
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
WE...
MADE IT.
INSTRUMENTS RETURNING
TO NORMAL, CAPTAIN.
ALL DECKS REPORT
DAMAGE AND CASUALTIES.
SEVERAL SYSTEMS
OUT, SIR.
OPERATING ON
EMERGENCY BACKUP.
NONE AFFECT
FLIGHT PROCEDURE.
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS
SUSTAINING ON EMERGENCY.
I'LL HAVE A FULL REPORT
ON SHIP'S STATUS FOR YOU
IN A MOMENT, SIR.
YOUR PEOPLE ARE
MOST EFFICIENT, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
SO ARE YOURS.
HANAR,
START THE
NEUTRALIZING
OPERATION.
WHAT NEUTRALIZING
OPERATION?
YOU HUMANS ARE
TROUBLESOME FOR US.
WE NEEDED YOU
TO GET US THROUGH
THE BARRIER.
BUT THERE AREN'T
ENOUGH OF US
TO EFFICIENTLY
GUARD ALL OF YOU
ALL OF THE TIME.
FURTHER, THE FOOD
SYNTHESIZERS
CANNOT MANUFACTURE
ENOUGH FOOD FOR
THE ENTIRE JOURNEY.
WE ARE THEREFORE
NEUTRALIZING
ALL NONESSENTIAL
PERSONNEL.
NO.
THE PROCEDURE
IS ALREADY UNDERWAY.
NOW, AS TO
BRIDGE PERSONNEL...
DREA.
WE HAVE NO NEED
FOR COMMUNICATION.
AND SINCE DREA
IS CAPABLE
OF HANDLING THE SHIP
FROM HERE ON...
DO YOU NOT AGREE THAT
THIS IS A BETTER THING
FOR THEM
THAN EXPLODING
THE SHIP
AS YOUR ENGINEER
HAD THOUGHT TO DO?
WE DETECTED IT,
OF COURSE.
TOMAR HAS
DEVISED A MECHANISM
TO PREVENT ANY
FURTHER TAMPERING.
PLEASE ACCEPT
YOUR SITUATION,
CAPTAIN.
IT WILL MAKE THINGS
MUCH LESS PAINFUL.
IS THIS ALL?
I HAVE REVIEWED
SHIP'S PERSONNEL,
CAPTAIN.
IT APPEARS WE FOUR
ARE THE ONLY ONES
THE KELVANS CONSIDER
ESSENTIAL.
SCOTTY TELLS ME
YOU COULD'VE
DESTROYED THE SHIP
IN THE BARRIER.
WHY DIDN'T YOU?
I COULDN'T.
IF THAT WAS OUR ONLY
CHANCE TO STOP--
I DIDN'T THINK
IT WAS.
JIM--
BONES, THAT'S ENOUGH!
JIM, I SAW THEM REDUCE
FOUR OF MY DOCTORS AND NURSES--
THEY REDUCED
THE WHOLE CREW!
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU TAKE THE TROUBLE
TO CONSUME
THIS BULK MATERIAL
TO SUSTAIN YOURSELVES.
WE HAVE ASCERTAINED
THAT THESE CONTAIN
ALL THE NUTRITIONAL
ELEMENTS.
BEFORE YOU CONDEMN IT,
WHY DON'T YOU TRY IT?
I BELIEVE I WILL.
ASSIST ME.
IT'S YOUR IDEA, DOCTOR.
GO AHEAD.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL SHOW YOU HOW
TO WORK THE SELECTOR.
SIR, WHY DON'T WE
TRY AGAIN
TO KNOCK OUT THE
PARALYSIS PROJECTOR?
I KNOW THE CASING
LOOKS IMPENETRABLE,
BUT I MAY BE ABLE
TO DO SOMETHING.
EVEN IF WE COULD,
IT'S OUT OF THE QUESTION.
WE NEED THAT PROJECTOR
TO BRING OUR PEOPLE
BACK TO HUMAN FORM.
THEN HOW WILL WE
STOP THE KELVANS?
Spock: CAPTAIN.
IT'S QUITE GOOD.
I'M DELIGHTED.
MOST CURIOUS.
WHAT IS?
THE ISOLATED GLIMPSES
OF THINGS I SAW
WHEN I TOUCHED
KELINDA'S MIND
ARE BEGINNING TO COALESCE
IN MY CONSCIOUSNESS.
THE KELVANS HAVE SUPERIOR
INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY.
TO ACHIEVE IT,
THEY HAVE APPARENTLY
SACRIFICED
ANYTHING WHICH WOULD
TEND TO DISTRACT THEM.
PERCEPTIVE SENSES
SUCH AS TASTE,
TOUCH, SMELL,
AND, OF COURSE, EMOTIONS.
BUT THEN TOMAR
SHOULDN'T BE ENJOYING
THE TASTE OF HIS FOOD.
YES.
QUITE CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
BUT THEY HAVE TAKEN
HUMAN FORM
AND ARE THEREFORE
HAVING HUMAN REACTION.
HMM.
IF HE KEEPS REACTING
LIKE THAT,
HE'S GONNA NEED A DIET.
IF THEY ALL RESPOND
TO STIMULATION OF THE SENSES,
THEN MAYBE WE CAN
DISTRACT THEM.
THEY CAN'T HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO HANDLE
THE SENSES YET.
IF WE CAN CONFUSE
THEM ENOUGH,
WE CAN GET THOSE DEVICES
FROM THEIR BELTS.
THAT SEEMS REASONABLE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT MAY BE
OUR ONLY CHANCE.
LOOK FOR ANY WAY
TO STIMULATE
THE SENSES.
I CAN THINK OF ONE WAY
RIGHT OFF.
LAD, YOU'RE GOING
TO NEED SOMETHING
TO WASH THAT
DOWN WITH.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
ANY SAURIAN BRANDY?
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THAT.
PLEASE ARTICULATE.
THAT BODY OF YOURS
IS A BIT ANEMIC.
COMES FROM TAKING
FOOD IN PILLS
INSTEAD OF
SOLID SUSTENANCE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GOING TO GIVE YOU
A SHOT.
HIGH POTENCY
VITAMIN CONCENTRATE.
YOU'LL NEED
THREE A DAY
FOR A FEW DAYS.
AND EAT SOME
SOLID FOOD, WILL YA?
NO MORE.
AM I DISTURBING YOU?
WHAT IS IT YOU WISH?
I...
WISH TO APOLOGIZE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
FOR HITTING YOU.
I'M SORRY.
THAT IS NOT NECESSARY.
YOU ATTEMPTED TO ESCAPE
AS WE WOULD HAVE.
YES, WELL, I...
DON'T USUALLY
GO AROUND
BEATING UP
BEAUTIFUL WOMEN.
WHY NOT?
WELL, THERE ARE
BETTER THINGS
FOR MEN AND WOMEN
TO DO.
LIKE WHAT?
IS THIS
WHERE I HIT YOU?
NO, THE OTHER SIDE.
OH.
I'M SORRY.
IS THAT BETTER?
BETTER?
WAS IT INTENDED
AS A REMEDY?
THIS IS.
IS THERE SOME
SIGNIFICANCE
TO THIS ACTION?
WELL, AMONG HUMANS,
IT'S, UH...
MEANT TO EXPRESS...
WARMTH AND LOVE.
OH.
YOU ARE TRYING
TO SEDUCE ME.
I HAVE BEEN
STUDYING YOU.
ME?
ALL HUMANS.
THIS BUSINESS
OF LOVE...
YOU HAVE DEVOTED
MUCH LITERATURE TO IT.
WHY DO YOU BUILD
SUCH A MYSTIQUE
AROUND A SIMPLE
BIOLOGICAL FUNCTION?
WE ENJOY IT.
THE LITERATURE?
KELINDA, I'M SORRY
I BROUGHT UP
THE WHOLE SUBJECT.
DO YOU
REALLY REGARD
THIS TOUCHING
OF THE LIPS
AS PLEASURABLE?
I DID.
CURIOUS.
LET ME TRY.
IS THERE
SOME PROBLEM, CAPTAIN?
NOT WHEN I CAME IN.
WHAT DID HE
WANT HERE?
HE CAME TO APOLOGIZE
FOR HITTING ME.
APPARENTLY IT INVOLVES
SOME PECULIAR
TOUCHING CONTACT.
IN WHAT MANNER?
VERY ODD CREATURES,
THESE HUMANS.
DO YOU HAVE MORE?
NOT OF THIS.
WELL, ANYTHING.
YES. HUMANS ARE
VERY PECULIAR.
I OFTEN FIND THEM
UNFATHOMABLE.
BUT AN INTERESTING
PSYCHOLOGICAL STUDY.
WELL, I DO NOT UNDERSTAND
THIS BUSINESS
OF PRESSING WITH
THE LIPS TO APOLOGIZE.
I BELIEVE YOU'RE
REFERRING TO A KISS.
BUT IT IS
MY UNDERSTANDING
THAT SUCH APOLOGIES
ARE USUALLY EXCHANGED
BETWEEN PEOPLE WHO HAVE
SOME AFFECTION
FOR EACH OTHER.
KELINDA HAS NO AFFECTION
FOR CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOUR GAME IS OFF.
ARE YOU DISTURBED
BY THE INCIDENT?
WHY SHOULD I
BE DISTURBED?
YOU'VE KNOWN KELINDA
FOR SOME TIME.
SHE'S A KELVAN
AS YOU ARE.
AMONG HUMANS,
I'VE FOUND THE SYMPTOMS
YOU'RE DISPLAYING
USUALLY
INDICATE JEALOUSY.
I HAVE NO REASON
FOR SUCH A REACTION.
KELINDA'S A FEMALE,
NOTHING MORE.
CAPTAIN KIRK
SEEMS TO FIND HER
QUITE ATTRACTIVE.
WELL, OF COURSE SHE IS!
YOU ARE NOT JEALOUS.
NO!
NOR UPSET.
CERTAINLY NOT.
CHECKMATE.
I FOUND THIS ON
GANYMOOD...
UH, GANYMEDE.
WHAT IS IT?
WELL, IT'S, UM...
IT'S GREEN.
KELINDA, I'VE
BEEN THINKING.
YES?
I DO NOT WISH YOU
TO FRATERNIZE
WITH ANY
OF THE HUMANS.
WHY NOT?
WELL, THEY...
THEY OFFER SUCH
STRANGE IDEAS.
THEY'RE NOT
MEANT FOR US.
NOT FOR KELVANS.
HAVE YOU GIVEN
THIS ORDER
TO THE OTHERS?
NO. I WISH YOU
TO PARTICULARLY
AVOID CAPTAIN KIRK.
I WILL NOT!
YOU HAVE TOLD ME
OVER AND OVER AGAIN
HUMANS ARE
NO THREAT TO US.
WE ARE SUPERIOR.
I WILL DO
AS I PLEASE.
YOU WILL DO AS I SAY,
OR I WILL NEUTRALIZE
YOUR CAPTAIN KIRK
AND ALL THE OTHER HUMANS
AS WELL.
HOW MANY MORE OF THESE?
WELL, NOW, LET'S SEE.
YOU'VE HAD
THREE SHOTS...
YOU BETTER STAY
ON THEM FOR A FEW DAYS,
AND THEN WE'LL SEE
HOW YOU'RE RESPONDING.
I SEE NO REASON FOR YOU
TO REFER TO YOURSELF
IN THE PLURAL.
YOU HAVE MORE?
ALL I HAVE
IS A BOTTLE OF
VERY, VERY, VERY
OLD SCOTCH.
WHISKEY!
WELL,
I WILL TRY IT.
I'LL GET IT!
[GLASS BREAKS]
I WAS
SAVING YOU FOR--
WHAT?
NEVER MIND.
HERE'S YOUR GLASS.
I CAN'T TELL
IF WE'RE GETTING ANYWHERE.
AND I HAVEN'T SEEN SCOTTY
IN HOURS.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN
TOMAR EITHER.
BUT MY MAN HANAR IS
GETTING MORE IRRITABLE
BY THE MINUTE.
I'M GIVING HIM
SHOTS OF FORMAZINE.
THAT SHOULD HAVE HIM
CLIMBING THE WALLS.
ROJAN HAS EXHIBITED
SYMPTOMS OF JEALOUSY.
I WOULD LIKE TO
SPEAK WITH YOU,
CAPTAIN.
DOCTOR,
I'M DUE FOR
ANOTHER INJECTION
OF STOKALINE.
HMM?
STOKALINE.
OH.
YOU WILL PARDON US.
YOU HAD SOMETHING
TO SAY?
YES.
THIS CULTURAL MYSTIQUE
SURROUNDING THE
BIOLOGICAL FUNCTION.
YES.
YOU REALIZE HUMANS
ARE OVERLY PREOCCUPIED
WITH THE SUBJECT.
YES. WE DO THINK
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT IT.
I'VE DONE SOME
SUPPLEMENTAL READING
ON IT,
AND, UH...
YOU HAVE A QUESTION?
YES.
I WAS WONDERING,
WOULD YOU PLEASE
APOLOGIZE TO ME AGAIN?
ROJAN, I WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
VERY WELL.
FIRST, I DO NOT
LIKE THE WAY
RESPONSIBILITY
AND DUTY HAS BEEN
PORTIONED OUT TO US.
IT'S THE WAY YOUR DUTIES
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN ASSIGNED.
THAT IS MY
SECOND QUARREL
WITH YOU.
HANAR!
FURTHER,
I DO NOT CARE MUCH
FOR THE WAY
YOU RUN THIS SHIP.
HANAR, CONFINE YOURSELF
TO YOUR QUARTERS!
OHHH, ROJAN HAS
FORBIDDEN ME TO SEE YOU.
YES, THAT'S TOO BAD.
WHY DO YOU DEFY HIM?
IT'S NOT A QUESTION
OF DEFIANCE.
WE WERE TOLD TO
FIND OUT EVERYTHING
WE COULD ABOUT YOU.
WELL, HOW'S
THE RESEARCH GOING?
I NEED SOME MORE
EXPERIMENTS.
MR. SPOCK, YOU WERE NOT
ORDERED TO THE BRIDGE.
WHAT IS
YOUR PURPOSE HERE?
AUTOMATIC SENSORS
AND VARIOUS OTHER
RECORDING DEVICES
REQUIRE MONITORING
AND PERIODIC ADJUSTMENTS.
VERY WELL. PROCEED.
HAVE YOU SEEN
CAPTAIN KIRK?
IF YOU WISH,
I SHALL CALL HIM
TO THE BRIDGE.
NO.
I WAS WONDERING
WHERE HE WAS.
I LEFT HIM IN
THE RECREATION ROOM.
HE WAS ALONE THEN.
NO, KELINDA
WAS WITH HIM.
SHE SEEMED ANXIOUS
TO SPEAK TO HIM.
I TOLD HER
TO STAY AWAY FROM HIM.
IT WOULD APPEAR, SIR,
THAT YOU HAVE LITTLE
CONTROL OVER HER.
OR PERHAPS...
CAPTAIN KIRK HAS MORE.
VERY INTERESTING.
BUT I FEEL RATHER...
STRANGE.
WE DID IT,
YOU AND ME.
PUT HIM RIGHT
UNDER THE TABLE.
I'LL TAKE THIS
TO THE CAPTAIN.
KELINDA, I TOLD YOU
TO AVOID THIS HUMAN.
I DID NOT WISH TO.
I AM YOUR COMMANDER.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH,
ROJAN.
YOU DID THIS TO HER,
CORRUPTED HER,
TURNED HER
AWAY FROM ME!
IF YOU CAN'T KEEP HER,
THAT'S NOT MY PROBLEM.
YOU WILL
RELEASE HER!
WHY DON'T YOU USE
YOUR PARALYZER?
YOU THOUGHT I WAS TAKING
YOUR WOMAN AWAY FROM YOU.
YOU'RE JEALOUS!
YOU TRIED TO KILL ME
WITH YOUR BARE HANDS.
WOULD A KELVAN DO THAT?
WOULD HE HAVE TO?
YOU'RE REACTING
WITH THE EMOTIONS
OF A HUMAN.
YOU ARE A HUMAN.
NO, I CANNOT BE!
I'M STIMULATING HIM.
YOU HAVE NO CHOICE.
TO USE THIS SHIP,
YOU HAVE TO USE
OUR FORM.
NOW YOU'RE
STUCK WITH IT,
YOU AND
YOUR DESCENDANTS
FOR THE NEXT
300 YEARS.
YOU FOOL!
THESE BODIES ARE TOOLS.
WE REMAIN KELVANS!
LOOK WHAT'S
HAPPENED TO YOU
IN THE SHORT TIME
YOU'VE BEEN
EXPOSED TO US.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
WILL HAPPEN
IN THREE CENTURIES?
WHEN THIS SHIP
GETS TO KELVA...
THE PEOPLE ON IT
WILL BE HUMAN.
THEY'LL BE ALIENS,
ENEMIES!
WE HAVE A DUTY...
OUR MISSION...
WE'VE GOT TO ACCOMPLISH
ANY WAY WE CAN.
YOUR MISSION IS
TO FIND NEW WORLDS
FOR YOUR PEOPLE
TO LIVE IN.
YOU CAN STILL
DO THAT.
WE CAN BRING
THIS PROBLEM
TO THE FEDERATION.
THERE ARE
MANY PLANETS
IN THIS GALAXY
THAT CAN
BE INHABITED.
YOU WOULD REALLY DO THAT?
YOU WOULD EXTEND WELCOME
TO INVADERS?
NO.
BUT WE WOULD
WELCOME FRIENDS.
ROJAN, YOU ARE ONLY
A LINK IN A CHAIN
FOLLOWING AN ORDER
GIVEN 300 YEARS AGO.
THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR YOU TO ESTABLISH
A DESTINY OF YOUR OWN.
PERHAPS.
PERHAPS IT COULD BE DONE.
A ROBOT SHIP
COULD BE SENT TO KELVA
WITH THE FEDERATION
PROPOSAL.
BUT...
IF WE RETAIN THIS FORM,
WHERE COULD WE
FIND A PLACE?
IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT LITTLE PLANET
YOU WERE ON
WAS KIND OF NICE.
AND YOU...
YOU WOULD WISH
TO REMAIN WITH HIM?
HE'S MOST INTERESTING.
BUT I WISH TO GO WITH YOU.
I BELIEVE I OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY.
MOST PLEASURABLE.
YES.
VERY CURIOUS.
YOU SEE, ROJAN,
BEING HUMAN DOES HAVE
CERTAIN ADVANTAGES.
BEING ABLE TO APPRECIATE
THE BEAUTY OF A FLOWER...
OR A WOMAN.
BRIDGE...
THIS IS ROJAN.
YES, COMMANDER.
I'M RETURNING
COMMAND OF THE SHIP
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU WILL FOLLOW
HIS ORDERS.
SIR?
TURN THE SHIP AROUND.
WE'RE GOING HOME.