APPROACHING PLANET
OMEGA IV, SIR.
OBJECT AHEAD.
ANOTHER VESSEL
IN PLANET ORBIT,
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT, SOUND ALERT.
AYE, SIR.
[ALARM]
Uhura:
ALL DECKS REPORT
READY, SIR.
LONG-RANGE SENSOR SCAN,
MR. SULU.
IT'S THE
U.S.S. EXETER, SIR.
TRY TO CONTACT HER,
LIEUTENANT.
AYE, SIR.
THE EXETER...
SHE WAS PATROLLING
IN THIS AREA
SIX MONTHS AGO.
I HADN'T HEARD
OF ANY TROUBLE.
RECEIVING NO RESPONSE
TO OUR SIGNAL, SIR.
THE SENSORS INDICATE
NO DAMAGE TO THE VESSEL,
CAPTAIN.
I SEE.
MAGNIFICATION FACTOR 3,
MR. SULU.
HOLD OUR POSITION
OUT HERE, MR. SULU.
LIEUTENANT,
HAVE MR. SPOCK, DR. McCOY,
AND LIEUTENANT GALLOWAY
REPORT TO THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
WE'LL BOARD
AND INVESTIGATE.
WE'RE LOCKED ONTO
THE EXETER'S
ENGINEERING
SECTION, CAPTAIN.
PHASERS ON HEAVY STUN.
ENERGIZE.
CAPTAIN.
JUST THE UNIFORMS
ARE LEFT.
AS IF THEY WERE IN THEM
WHEN...
EXACTLY.
WHAT?
Captain Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
IS THERE ANYONE ON BOARD?
IF THERE IS,
AND YOU CAN HEAR ME,
PLEASE RESPOND BY INTERCOM
TO THE ENGINEERING SECTION.
IS THERE ANYONE ON BOARD?
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT GALLOWAY
AND I ARE CHECKING OUT
THE LOWER LEVELS.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
NO ONE ABOARD...
ONLY UNIFORMS.
WHAT ABOUT
THE SHUTTLECRAFT?
GALLOWAY ON THE HANGAR DECK,
SIR.
ALL FOUR OF THE CRAFT
ARE STILL HERE.
IF THEY LEFT,
THEY DIDN'T LEAVE THAT WAY.
DR. McCOY AND I
ARE GOING TO THE BRIDGE.
MEET US THERE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
ABOARD THE U.S.S. EXETER
COMMANDED BY RON TRACEY,
ONE OF THE MOST
EXPERIENCED CAPTAINS
IN THE STARFLEET.
WHAT COULD HAVE HAPPENED
TO HIM
AND THE OVER 400 MEN AND WOMEN
WHO WERE ON THIS SHIP?
THE HELM WAS LEFT
ON AUTOMATIC, SIR.
FASCINATING.
SPOCK...
PLAY THE LAST LOG TAPE.
MAYBE THEY HAD TIME
TO RECORD WHAT HAPPENED
TO THEM.
AYE, SIR.
JIM, THE ANALYSIS
OF THIS SO FAR
IS POTASSIUM--35%,
CARBON--18%,
PHOSPHOROUS--1.0,
CALCIUM--1.5.
JIM, THE CREW
DIDN'T LEAVE.
THEY'RE STILL HERE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THESE WHITE
CRYSTALS--
THAT'S WHAT'S LEFT
OF THE HUMAN BODY
WHEN YOU TAKE
THE WATER AWAY,
WHICH MAKES UP 96%
OF OUR BODIES.
WITHOUT WATER,
WE'RE ALL JUST
3 OR 4 POUNDS
OF CHEMICALS.
NOW, SOMETHING
CRYSTALLIZED THEM
DOWN TO THIS.
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
I HAVE THEIR SURGEON'S LOG,
CAPTAIN.
THEIR LAST LOG ENTRY,
ON SCREEN.
IF YOU'VE COME ABOARD
THIS SHIP...
[GASPING]
YOU'RE DEAD MEN.
DON'T GO BACK
TO YOUR OWN SHIP.
[GASPING]
YOU HAVE ONE CHANCE.
GET DOWN THERE.
GET DOWN THERE FAST.
CAPTAIN TRACEY IS...
AAH!
PREPARE TO BEAM DOWN
TO THE PLANET SURFACE--
FAST.
[VOICES]
AAH!
[SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
AAH!
[SPEAKING
NATIVE LANGUAGE]
PUT THE AX AWAY, LIYANG.
Captain Kirk:
THAT'S RON TRACEY.
RON.
I KNEW SOMEONE WOULD
COME LOOKING FOR US.
I'M JUST SORRY
IT HAD TO BE YOU, JIM.
I'M GLAD YOUR ARRIVAL
STOPPED THIS.
NO MORE OF THIS, WU.
LOCK UP THE SAVAGES.
THEY CARRY FIREBOXES.
I SAID LOCK UP
THE SAVAGES.
THE PRISONERS
ARE CALLED YANGS.
IMPOSSIBLE EVEN
TO COMMUNICATE WITH.
HORDES OF THEM OUT THERE.
THEY'LL ATTACK ANYTHING
THAT MOVES.
INTERESTING THAT
THE VILLAGERS KNOW
ABOUT PHASERS.
YOU WERE LEFT ALONE
DOWN HERE.
RON...
WHAT HAPPENED?
OUR MEDI-SCANNERS
REVEALED THIS PLANET
AS PERFECTLY HARMLESS.
THE VILLAGERS,
THE KOHNS HERE,
WERE FRIENDLY ENOUGH
ONCE THEY GOT OVER
THE SHOCK OF MY WHITE SKIN.
AS YOU'VE SEEN,
WE RESEMBLE THE YANGS--
THE SAVAGES.
MY LANDING PARTY
TRANSPORTED BACK
TO THE SHIP.
I STAYED DOWN HERE TO ARRANGE
FOR THE PLANET SURVEY
WITH THE VILLAGE ELDERS.
THE NEXT THING I KNEW,
THE SHIP WAS CALLING ME.
THE LANDING PARTY HAD TAKEN
AN UNKNOWN DISEASE BACK.
MY CREW, JIM.
MY ENTIRE CREW...GONE.
YES, I KNOW.
WE SAW IT.
AND I'M JUST AS INFECTED
AS THEY WERE...
AS YOU ARE,
BUT I STAYED ALIVE
BECAUSE I STAYED DOWN HERE.
THERE'S SOME
NATURAL IMMUNIZATION
THAT PROTECTS EVERYONE
ON THE PLANET SURFACE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
LUCKY WE FOUND THAT LOG
REPORT.
IF WE'D GONE BACK TO
THE ENTERPRISE...
YOU'D BE DYING BY NOW,
ALONG WITH THE REST
OF THE ENTERPRISE CREW.
YOU'LL STAY ALIVE
ONLY AS LONG
AS YOU STAY HERE.
NONE OF US
WILL EVER LEAVE
THIS PLANET.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE ENTERPRISE HAS LEFT
THE EXETER AND HAS MOVED
INTO CLOSE PLANET ORBIT.
ALTHOUGH IT APPEARS THE
INFECTION MAY STRAND US
HERE THE REST OF OUR LIVES,
I FACE AN EVEN MORE
DIFFICULT PROBLEM--
THE GROWING BELIEF
THAT CAPTAIN TRACEY
HAS BEEN INTERFERING
WITH THE EVOLUTION OF LIFE
ON THIS PLANET.
IT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE.
A STAR CAPTAIN'S
MOST SOLEMN OATH
IS THAT HE WILL GIVE
HIS LIFE,
EVEN HIS ENTIRE CREW,
RATHER THAN VIOLATE
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
TELL THE LAB
THE FINAL READING
ON OUR TISSUE
IS Y-3, X-POINT, 004,
AND I CAN USE A SECOND
BLOOD-ANALYZER UNIT.
WE'LL BEAM IT DOWN SHORTLY,
DOCTOR.
ENTERPRISE OUT.
OUR TISSUES
DEFINITELY SHOW
A MASSIVE
INFECTION, JIM,
BUT SOMETHING
IS IMMUNIZING US
DOWN HERE,
THANK HEAVENS,
OR WE'D
HAVE BEEN DEAD
HOURS AGO.
I DON'T THINK WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TIME TO ISOLATE IT,
BONES.
THE PROBLEM IS
IT COULD BE ANYTHING--
SOME SPORES
OR POLLEN IN THE AIR,
SOME CHEMICAL.
JUST FINDING IT
COULD TAKE MONTHS,
MAYBE EVEN YEARS,
AND I'VE ONLY GOT
ONE LEAD--
THE INFECTION RESEMBLES
ONE DEVELOPED BY EARTH
DURING THEIR
BACTERIOLOGICAL WARFARE
EXPERIMENTS
IN THE 1990s.
HARD TO BELIEVE WE
WERE ONCE FOOLISH ENOUGH
TO PLAY AROUND
WITH THAT.
[DOOR OPENS]
A YANG LANCE, DOCTOR.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
BRUISED ONLY.
WE WERE APPROXIMATELY
100 METERS
FROM THE VILLAGE
WHEN FIVE OF THE
SAVAGES AMBUSHED US.
WE MANAGED TO ESCAPE
WITHOUT FIRING.
SPOCK,
DO YOU SEE ANY HOPE
THAT THESE YANGS
CAN BE REASONED WITH?
A TRUCE,
A PARLEY, A--
NO, CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE TOO WILD.
THEY ACT ALMOST INSANE.
CAPTAIN TRACEY
IS BEING QUITE FACTUAL
IN SEVERAL STATEMENTS.
1--THE YANGS
ARE TOTALLY CONTEMPTUOUS
OF DEATH.
THEY SEEM
INCREDIBLY VICIOUS.
2--HE IS ALSO
BEING FACTUAL
IN THAT THE YANGS
ARE MASSING FOR AN ATTACK.
THERE ARE SIGNS
OF THOUSANDS OF THEM
IN THE FOOTHILLS BEYOND.
HOWEVER, HE WAS LESS
THAN TRUTHFUL
IN ONE VERY
IMPORTANT MATTER...
PHASER POWER PACKS.
CAPTAIN TRACEY'S
RESERVE BELT PACKS--
EMPTY.
FOUND AMONG THE REMAINS
OF SEVERAL HUNDRED
YANG BODIES.
THE FOOL.
A SMALLER ATTACK
ON THIS VILLAGE
A WEEK AGO,
DRIVEN OFF BY CAPTAIN TRACEY
WITH HIS PHASER.
I HAVE FOUND VILLAGERS
WHO WILL CORROBORATE IT.
NOW WAIT A MINUTE.
HE LOST HIS SHIP
AND HIS CREW,
AND THEN HE FOUND HIMSELF
THE ONLY THING STANDING
BETWEEN AN ENTIRE VILLAGE
OF PLEASANT, PEACEFUL PEOPLE.
REGULATIONS
ARE QUITE HARSH,
BUT THEY'RE ALSO
QUITE CLEAR, CAPTAIN.
IF YOU DO NOT ACT,
YOU WILL BE CONSIDERED
EQUALLY GUILTY.
WITHOUT A SERUM,
WE'RE TRAPPED HERE
WITH THE VILLAGERS.
WHY DESTROY
WHAT'S LEFT OF THE MAN
BY ARRESTING HIM?
I AGREE THAT FORMAL CHARGES
HAVE LITTLE MEANING NOW.
HOWEVER, YOU MUST AT LEAST,
CONFISCATE HIS PHASER.
THE FOOL.
STARFLEET SHOULD BE
MADE AWARE.
[DOOR OPENS]
I'LL BE SENDING
THE NEXT MESSAGE, JIM.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
ENTERPRISE BRIDGE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
CAPTAIN TRACEY
OF THE EXETER.
YES, SIR. CAPTAIN KIRK
INFORMED US EARLIER
YOU HAD SURVIVED.
I'M AFRAID I HAVE SOME
BAD NEWS FOR YOU.
YOUR CAPTAIN
AND LANDING PARTY
MUST HAVE BEAMED DOWN
TOO LATE FOR FULL
IMMUNIZATION.
THEY'VE BEEN FOUND
UNCONSCIOUS,
BUT I'M DOING EVERYTHING
I CAN FOR THEM NOW.
SIR, THIS IS LIEUTENANT SULU
IN TEMPORARY COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
OUR WHOLE MEDICAL STAFF
WILL VOLUNTEER
TO BEAM DOWN.
THERE'S NO POINT
IN RISKING MORE LIVES,
LIEUTENANT,
SINCE I HAVE ACQUIRED
SOME IMMUNITY--
SULU!
AT THEIR NEXT WORD,
KILL HIM.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
Sulu:
REPEAT YOUR MESSAGE.
COME IN, LANDING PARTY.
I'M SORRY, LIEUTENANT.
YOUR CAPTAIN'S FEVERISH,
QUITE DELIRIOUS.
I UNDERSTAND, SIR.
WHEN HE REGAINS
CONSCIOUSNESS,
ASSURE HIM THAT WE HAVE
NO PROBLEMS HERE.
I'LL CONTACT YOU LATER,
LET YOU KNOW OF
ANY FUTURE NEEDS.
LANDING PARTY OUT.
THAT'S ENOUGH OF THAT,
CAPTAIN.
LEAVE US.
CAPTAIN RONALD TRACEY,
AS PER STARFLEET COMMAND,
REGULATION 7,
PARAGRAPH 4...
I MUST NOW
CONSIDER MYSELF
UNDER ARREST,
UNLESS IN THE PRESENCE
OF THE MOST SENIOR
FELLOW OFFICERS
PRESENTLY AVAILABLE,
I GIVE SATISFACTORY
ANSWER TO THOSE CHARGES
WHICH YOU NOW BRING...
ET CETERA, ET CETERA.
THOSE ARE THE FIRST
WORDS DUTY REQUIRED YOU
TO SAY TO ME,
AND YOU SAID THEM.
YOU'RE COVERED.
NOW SUPPOSE WE GO ON
TO THE NEXT SUBJECT...
WHICH IS...
WHY?
GOOD.
DIRECT, SUCCINCT.
ANSWER--
NO NATIVE TO THIS PLANET
HAS EVER HAD ANY TRACE
OF ANY KIND OF DISEASE.
HOW LONG WOULD A MAN
LIVE IF ALL DISEASE
WERE ERASED, JIM?
WU.
TELL CAPTAIN KIRK
YOUR AGE.
AGE?
I HAVE SEEN 42 YEARS
OF THE REDBIRD--
THEIR YEAR OF THE REDBIRD
COMES ONCE EVERY 11 YEARS,
WHICH HE'S SEEN 42 TIMES.
MULTIPLY IT.
WU IS 462 YEARS OLD.
HIS FATHER
IS WELL OVER 1,000.
INTERESTED, JIM?
McCOY COULD VERIFY
ALL THAT.
HE WILL IF YOU ORDER IT.
WE MUST HAVE A DOCTOR
RESEARCHING THIS.
ARE YOU GRASPING
ALL IT MEANS?
THIS IMMUNIZING
AGENT HERE, ONCE
WE'VE FOUND IT,
IS A FOUNTAIN OF YOUTH--
VIRTUAL IMMORTALITY,
OR AS MUCH AS ANY MAN
WILL EVER WANT.
FOR SALE BY...
OUT.
BY THOSE WHO OWN
THE SERUM.
McCOY WILL EVENTUALLY
ISOLATE IT.
MEANWHILE,
YOU INFORM YOUR SHIP
YOUR SITUATION'S
IMPOSSIBLE.
ORDER THEM AWAY.
WHEN WE'RE READY,
WE'LL BARGAIN FOR
A WHOLE FLEET OF SHIPS
TO PICK US UP,
AND THEY'LL DO IT.
YES, I SUPPOSE THEY WOULD.
BUT WE'VE GOT
TO STAY ALIVE.
LET THE YANGS KILL US
AND DESTROY WHAT WE
HAVE TO OFFER,
AND WE'LL HAVE
COMMITTED A CRIME
AGAINST ALL HUMANITY.
I'D SAY THAT'S SLIGHTLY
MORE IMPORTANT
THAN THE PRIME
DIRECTIVE...
WOULDN'T YOU, JIM?
THAT'S A VERY INTERESTING
PROPOSITION.
LET ME THINK IT OVER.
GUARDS.
TAKE THE DOCTOR BACK
TO HIS WORKPLACE.
THE POINTED-EARED ONE
STAYS,
AND, WU, TELL YOUR MEN
WE'LL BE LEAVING SOON.
WE'LL BE IN AMBUSH
FOR THE YANGS...
WITH MANY FIREBOXES
THIS TIME.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT,
JIM?
YAH!
ANIMALS WHO HAPPEN
TO LOOK LIKE US.
YOU STILL THINK
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE'S
FOR THIS PLANET?
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE
THE RIGHT OR THE WISDOM
TO INTERFERE
HOWEVER A PLANET
IS EVOLVING.
WELL, IF LOGIC WON'T WORK,
PERHAPS THIS WILL.
PUT HIM IN THERE.
AAGH!
[PUNCHING]
[GASPING]
[SNORING]
AAH!
[GRUNTING]
DON'T THEY EVER REST?
NOT THAT I HAVE OBSERVED,
CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE,
SHOULD THEY WISH
TO DO SO,
ONE COULD ALWAYS REST
WHILE THE OTHER
KEEPS YOU OCCUPIED.
THANK YOU, SPOCK.
AAH!
PLEASE TELL ME
WHY YOU WANT
TO KILL ME?
GOOD, CAPTAIN.
TRY TO REASON WITH THEM.
KEEP TRYING, CAPTAIN.
THEIR BEHAVIOR
IS HIGHLY ILLOGICAL.
NO POINT IN REPEATING
THAT IT'S ILLOGICAL, SPOCK.
I'M QUITE AWARE OF IT.
AAH!
PITY YOU CAN'T
TEACH ME THAT.
I HAVE TRIED, CAPTAIN.
HMM?
OH, THANK YOU...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CAPTAIN,
I HAVE MANAGED
TO LOOSEN THIS GRILL
SOMEWHAT.
IF THE MORTAR ON YOURS
IS AS OLD...
I CAN'T EVEN GET AT IT.
THEY'D BE ON ME
IN A MOMENT.
KEEP TALKING, SPOCK.
DON'T LET ME DOZE OFF.
CAPTAIN TRACEY MENTIONED
THERE WAS ONCE
A CONSIDERABLE
CIVILIZATION HERE.
THE ONLY
REASONABLE EXPLANATION
WOULD BE A WAR--
A NUCLEAR DEVASTATION
OR A BACTERIOLOGICAL
HOLOCAUST.
THAT'S A VERY
INTERESTING THEORY.
THE YELLOW CIVILIZATION
IS ALMOST DESTROYED.
THE WHITE CIVILIZATION
IS DESTROYED.
KEEP WORKING ON
THE WINDOW
IF WE'RE EVER GOING TO
REGAIN OUR FREEDOM.
FREEDOM?
SPOCK.
YES, I HEARD, CAPTAIN.
THAT IS A WORSHIP WORD.
YANG WORSHIP.
YOU WILL NOT SPEAK IT.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
IT IS...
OUR WORSHIP WORD, TOO.
YOU LIVE WITH THE KOHNS.
AM I NOT NOW
A PRISONER OF THE KOHNS
AS YOU ARE?
WHY DID YOU NOT SPEAK
UNTIL NOW?
YOU SPOKE TO KOHNS.
THEY ARE ONLY
FOR KILLING.
SPOCK, WE'LL HAVE YOU OUT
IN A MINUTE.
CAPTAIN?
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN...
ARE YOU ABLE TO RESPOND?
SPOCK.
HOW LONG?
7 HOURS AND 8 MINUTES,
CAPTAIN.
7 HOURS...
AND 8...
SPOCK...
KEYS.
I'LL HAVE YOU OUT
IN A MINUTE.
[SCRAPING SOUNDS]
OH.
GOOD MORNING, JIM.
GOOD MORNING.
WE CAN CONTACT THE SHIP
IN A FEW MOMENTS, CAPTAIN,
IF I CAN CROSS-CIRCUIT
THIS UNIT.
GOOD.
FIND OUT ANYTHING?
YES. I'M CONVINCED
THAT ONCE
THERE WAS A FRIGHTENING
BIOLOGICAL WAR THAT
EXISTED HERE.
THE VIRUS STILL EXISTS.
THEN OVER THE YEARS,
NATURE BUILT UP THESE
NATURAL IMMUNIZING AGENTS
IN THE FOOD, THE
WATER, AND THE SOIL.
WAR CREATED AN IMBALANCE
AND NATURE
COUNTERBALANCED IT.
THERE IS A DISEASE
HERE, SOMETHING
THAT AFFECTED
THE EXETER
LANDING PARTY
AND US.
THAT'S RIGHT. THESE
IMMUNIZING AGENTS TAKE TIME.
AND THAT'S THE REAL TRAGEDY.
HAD THE EXETER
LANDING PARTY STAYED HERE
JUST A FEW HOURS LONGER,
THEY NEVER
WOULD HAVE DIED.
THEN WE CAN LEAVE
ANY TIME WE WANT TO.
TRACEY IS
OF THE OPINION
THAT THESE IMMUNIZING
AGENTS CAN BECOME
A FOUNTAIN OF YOUTH.
THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE
OVER 1,000 YEARS OLD,
BONES.
SURVIVAL OF THE FITTEST,
BECAUSE THEIR ANCESTORS
WHO SURVIVED
HAD TO HAVE
A SUPERIOR RESISTANCE.
THEN THEY BUILT UP
THESE POWERFUL
PROTECTIVE ANTIBODIES
IN THE BLOOD
DURING THE WARS.
NOW, IF YOU WANT
TO DESTROY A CIVILIZATION
OR A WHOLE WORLD,
PERHAPS YOUR DESCENDANTS
MIGHT DEVELOP A LONGER LIFE,
BUT I HARDLY THINK
IT'S WORTH IT.
THEN ANYTHING
YOU DEVELOP HERE
AS A RESULT OF ALL THIS
IS USELESS.
WELL, WHO KNOWS?
IT MIGHT EVENTUALLY
CURE THE COMMON COLD,
BUT LENGTHEN LIVES?
POPPYCOCK.
I CAN DO MORE FOR YOU
IF YOU JUST EAT RIGHT
AND EXERCISE REGULARLY.
Spock: READY, CAPTAIN.
QUITE CRUDE.
VOICE COMMUNICATION
WILL NOT BE POSSIBLE,
BUT WE CAN
SIGNAL THE SHIP.
ALL THAT BLOODSHED
FOR NOTHING.
THAT'LL BE SUFFICIENT,
MR. SPOCK.
NO MESSAGES.
KIRK, THE SAVAGE
IN THE CELL WITH YOU...
DID YOU SET HIM FREE?
THE SAVAGE, KIRK--YOU SENT
HIM TO WARN THE TRIBES!
THE YANGS
MUST BE WARNED.
THEY SACRIFICED HUNDREDS
JUST TO DRAW US
OUT IN THE OPEN.
AND THEN THEY CAME...
AND THEY CAME.
WE DRAINED
FOUR OF OUR PHASERS,
AND THEY STILL CAME.
WE KILLED THOUSANDS,
HE'LL LIVE, BUT I'LL
HAVE TO GET HIM
TO BETTER FACILITIES
THAN THIS.
IMPOSSIBLE!
YOU CAN'T CARRY THE DISEASE
UP TO THE SHIP WITH YOU.
HE'S FULLY
IMMUNIZED NOW.
WE ALL ARE.
WE CAN BEAM UP
AT ANY TIME.
ANY OF US.
YOU'VE ISOLATED THE SERUM?
THERE'S NO SERUM!
THERE ARE NO MIRACLES!
THERE'S NO IMMORTALITY HERE!
ALL THIS
IS FOR NOTHING!
EXPLAIN IT TO HIM,
DOCTOR.
LEAVE MEDICINE
TO MEDICAL MEN, CAPTAIN.
YOU FOUND
NO FOUNTAIN OF YOUTH HERE.
PEOPLE LIVE LONGER HERE NOW
BECAUSE IT'S NATURAL
FOR THEM TO.
OUTSIDE.
OR I'LL BURN DOWN
BOTH YOUR FRIENDS NOW.
DO WHAT YOU CAN
FOR HIM, DOCTOR.
WHERE IS EVERYBODY?
DEAD OR IN HIDING.
NOW LET'S SEE HOW EAGER
YOU ARE TO DIE.
CALL YOUR SHIP.
I NEED YOUR HELP, KIRK.
THEY'RE GOING
TO ATTACK THE VILLAGE.
MY PHASER'S ALMOST DRAINED.
WE NEED NEW FRESH ONES.
YOU'RE NOT JUST
GONNA STAND THERE
AND LET THEM KILL YOU,
ARE YOU?
IF I PUT A WEAPON
IN YOUR HAND, YOU'LL
FIGHT, WON'T YOU?
WE CAN BEAM UP, TRACEY.
ALL OF US!
I WANT FIVE PHASERS.
NO, 10...
WITH THREE EXTRA
POWER PACKS EACH.
ALL RIGHT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT NOW?
YES,
QUITE ALL RIGHT.
I'D LIKE 10 PHASERS
BEAMED DOWN
WITH THREE
EXTRA POWER PACKS,
PLEASE.
HAVE YOU GOT THAT?
Say again.
ENTERPRISE,
DO YOU READ ME?
CAPTAIN, THIS IS SULU.
WE READ YOU,
BUT SURELY YOU KNOW
THAT CAN'T BE DONE
WITHOUT VERIFICATION.
NOT EVEN IF WE'RE
IN DANGER, MR. SULU?
CAPTAIN, WE HAVE
VOLUNTEERS STANDING BY
TO BEAM DOWN.
WHAT IS YOUR SITUATION?
THE SITUATION...
IS NOT IMMEDIATELY
DANGEROUS.
HAVE THE VOLUNTEERS
STAND BY. KIRK OUT.
YOU HAVE
A WELL-TRAINED
BRIDGE CREW, CAPTAIN.
MY COMPLIMENTS.
[CLICK]
[APPLAUSE AND CHEERS]
[WHOOPING]
SPOCK?
I'M WEAK, CAPTAIN,
BUT NOT IN DIFFICULTY.
HE MUST HAVE
ATTENTION SOON.
MY NEED FOR ATTENTION
IS VITAL, DOCTOR,
BUT OUR NEED
FOR DEPARTURE
IS EVEN MORE IMMEDIATE.
IF MY ANCESTORS
WERE FORCED OUT
OF THE CITIES
INTO THE DESERTS,
THE HILLS...
YES. I SEE, CAPTAIN.
THEY WOULD'VE LEARNED
TO WEAR SKINS,
ADOPTED
STOIC MANNERISMS,
LEARNED THE BOW
AND THE LANCE.
LIVING LIKE
THE INDIANS,
FINALLY EVEN
LOOKING LIKE
THE AMERICAN INDIAN.
AMERI...
YANGS?
YANKS?
SPOCK?
YANKEES!
KOHNS?
COMMUNISTS?
THE PARALLEL
IS ALMOST TOO CLOSE,
CAPTAIN.
IT WOULD MEAN
THEY FOUGHT THE WAR
YOUR EARTH AVOIDED,
AND IN THIS CASE,
THE ASIATICS WON
AND TOOK OVER
THIS PLANET.
BUT IF IT WERE TRUE...
ALL THESE GENERATIONS
OF YANKS
FIGHTING TO REGAIN
THEIR LAND...
YOU'RE A ROMANTIC, JIM.
[DRUM BEATS]
THAT WHICH IS OURS
IS OURS AGAIN.
IT WILL NEVER
BE TAKEN FROM US AGAIN.
THEY CAN BE HANDLED, JIM.
TOGETHER IT'LL BE EASY.
I CAUTION YOU, GENTLEMEN,
DON'T FIGHT ME HERE.
I'LL WIN.
OR AT WORST,
I'LL DRAG YOU DOWN WITH ME.
I AM CLOUD WILLIAM...
CHIEF.
ALSO SON OF CHIEF.
GUARDIAN OF THE HOLIES,
SPEAKER OF THE HOLY WORDS,
LEADER OF WARRIORS.
MANY HAVE DIED,
BUT THIS IS THE LAST
OF THE KOHN PLACES.
WHAT IS OURS...
IS OURS AGAIN.
AY PLEDGLI
IANECTU FLAGGEN...
TUPEP KILEFOR STAHN...
AND TO THE REPUBLIC
FOR WHICH IT STANDS,
ONE NATION,
UNDER GOD,
INDIVISIBLE,
WITH LIBERTY
AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
[ASTONISHED MURMURS]
HE SPOKE THE HOLY WORD.
YOU KNOW MANY
OF OUR HIGH-WORSHIP WORDS.
HOW?
IN MY LAND, WE HAVE
A TRIBE LIKE YOU.
WHERE IS YOUR TRIBE?
UP THERE. ONE OF THOSE
POINTS OF LIGHT
THAT YOU SEE AT NIGHT.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
WERE YOU CAST OUT?
YOU'RE CONFUSING THE STARS
WITH HEAVEN.
HE WAS CAST OUT!
DON'T YOU RECOGNIZE
THE EVIL ONE?
WHO ELSE WOULD TRICK YOU
WITH YOUR OWN SACRED WORDS?
LET YOUR GOD
STRIKE ME DEAD IF I LIE.
BUT HE WON'T,
BECAUSE I SPEAK FOR HIM.
YET YOU KILLED
MANY YANGS.
YOU TRIED TO KILL ME!
WE'RE NOT GODS!
WE'RE NOT EVIL ONES.
WE'RE MEN,
LIKE YOURSELVES.
WOULD A MAN KNOW
YOUR HOLY WORDS?
COULD A MAN USE THEM
TO TRICK YOU?
SEE HIS SERVANT.
HIS FACE, HIS EYES,
HIS EARS!
DO THE YANG LEGENDS
DESCRIBE THE SERVANT
OF THE EVIL ONE?
ARE YOUR FACES ALIKE?
CAN YOU TELL FROM THEM
WHICH OF YOU IS GOOD
AND WHICH OF YOU IS EVIL?
YOU COMMAND HIM.
EVERYONE'S SEEN THAT.
YOU WANT MORE PROOF?
HE HAS NO HEART.
HIS HEART IS DIFFERENT!
INTERNAL ORGANS
OF A VULCAN ARE--
BRING HIM.
HE HAS NO HEART.
ONE OF THEM LIES.
BUT WHICH?
IF WE SHOULD
KILL THE GOOD,
THE EVIL
WOULD BE AMONG US.
THERE IS A WAY.
THE GREATEST OF HOLIES.
CHIEFS AND SONS OF CHIEFS
MAY SPEAK THE WORDS,
BUT THE EVIL ONE'S TONGUE
WOULD SURELY TURN TO FIRE.
I WILL BEGIN...
AND YOU SHALL FINISH.
Ee'D PLEBNISTA
NORKOHN FORKOHN
PERFECTUNUN.
THOSE WORDS ARE FAMILIAR.
WAIT A MOMENT.
HE FEARS TO SPEAK THEM,
FOR INDEED HIS TONGUE
WOULD BURN WITH FIRE.
FORCE HIM!
KILL HIS SERVANT
UNLESS HE SPEAKS,
SO WE MAY SEE
IF THE WORDS BURN HIM.
WAIT!
THERE'S A BETTER WAY.
DOES NOT
YOUR SACRED BOOK
PROMISE THAT GOOD
IS STRONGER THAN EVIL?
YES, IT IS WRITTEN.
GOOD SHALL ALWAYS
DESTROY EVIL.
IT IS WRITTEN.
THE FIGHT IS DONE
WHEN ONE IS DEAD.
SPOCK, I'VE FOUND THAT EVIL
USUALLY TRIUMPHS...
UNLESS GOOD IS VERY,
VERY CAREFUL.
HOOWAH!
SPOCK, WE'VE GOT
TO DO SOMETHING!
I'M OPEN
TO SUGGESTIONS, DOCTOR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M MAKING A SUGGESTION.
KILL HIM.
IT IS WRITTEN--
GOOD MUST DESTROY EVIL.
SIR, WE PICKED UP
COMMUNICATOR SIGNALS--
WE'LL DISCUSS THAT
LATER, LIEUTENANT.
LESLIE,
FREE DR. McCOY
AND MR. SPOCK.
PUT CAPTAIN TRACEY
UNDER ARREST.
AYE, SIR.
NOW...
CLOUD WILLIAM.
YOU ARE
A GREAT GOD SERVANT.
WE ARE YOUR SLAVES.
GET UP.
FACE ME.
WHEN YOU WOULD NOT
SAY THE HOLY WORDS,
OF THE Ee'd PLEBNISTA,
I DOUBTED YOU.
I DID NOT RECOGNIZE
THOSE WORDS,
YOU SAID THEM SO BADLY--
WITHOUT MEANING.
NO! NO!
ONLY THE EYES
OF A CHIEF
MAY SEE
THE Ee'D PLEBNISTA.
THIS WAS NOT
WRITTEN FOR CHIEFS.
[SHOUTING]
HEAR ME!
HEAR THIS!
AMONG MY PEOPLE,
WE CARRY MANY SUCH WORDS
AS THIS
FROM MANY LANDS,
MANY WORLDS.
MANY ARE EQUALLY GOOD
AND ARE AS WELL RESPECTED,
BUT WHEREVER WE HAVE GONE,
NO WORDS HAVE SAID
THIS THING OF IMPORTANCE...
IN QUITE THIS WAY.
LOOK AT THESE THREE WORDS
WRITTEN LARGER
THAN THE REST
WITH A SPECIAL PRIDE
NEVER WRITTEN BEFORE OR SINCE--
TALL WORDS
PROUDLY SAYING...
"WE THE PEOPLE."
THAT WHICH YOU CALLED
Ee'D PLEBNISTA
WAS NOT WRITTEN
FOR CHIEFS OR KINGS
OR THE WARRIORS
OR THE RICH AND POWERFUL,
BUT FOR ALL THE PEOPLE!
DOWN THE CENTURIES,
YOU HAVE SLURRED
THE MEANING OF THE WORDS
"WE THE PEOPLE
OF THE UNITED STATES,
"IN ORDER TO FORM
A MORE PERFECT UNION,
"ESTABLISH JUSTICE, ENSURE
DOMESTIC TRANQUILITY,
"PROVIDE FOR THE COMMON
DEFENSE,
"PROMOTE
THE GENERAL WELFARE,
"AND SECURE
THE BLESSINGS OF LIBERTY
"TO OURSELVES
AND OUR POSTERITY...
DO ORDAIN AND ESTABLISH
THIS CONSTITUTION."
THESE WORDS
AND THE WORDS THAT FOLLOW
WERE NOT WRITTEN
ONLY FOR THE YANGS,
BUT FOR THE KOHNS
AS WELL!
THE KOHNS?
THEY MUST APPLY
TO EVERYONE
OR THEY MEAN NOTHING!
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
I DO NOT FULLY
UNDERSTAND,
ONE NAMED KIRK.
BUT THE HOLY WORDS
WILL BE OBEYED.
I SWEAR IT.
THERE'S NO QUESTION
ABOUT HIS GUILT, CAPTAIN,
BUT DOES
OUR INVOLVEMENT HERE
ALSO CONSTITUTE A VIOLATION
OF THE PRIME DIRECTIVE?
WE MERELY
SHOWED THEM
THE MEANING
OF WHAT THEY WERE
FIGHTING FOR.
LIBERTY AND FREEDOM
HAVE TO BE MORE THAN
JUST WORDS.
GENTLEMEN,
THE FIGHTING
IS OVER HERE.
I SUGGEST
WE LEAVE THEM
TO DISCOVER
THEIR HISTORY...
AND THEIR LIBERTY.