STANDARD ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
NOT NOW, LESLIE.
LIEUTENANT,
CONTACT THE SPACE STATION.
CAPTAIN, THE STATION
IS CALLING US.
ALL RIGHT. PUT THEM ON.
Captain Kirk,
this is Commodore Enright.
YES, COMMODORE.
I'D LIKE AN EXPLANATION.
The explanation
is beaming aboard now, Captain.
He may already be
in your transporter room.
SPOCK.
BOB.
ARE YOU SURPRISED?
I'LL SAY.
SPOCK, THIS IS--
COMMODORE WESLEY.
HOW DO YOU DO, SIR?
MR. SPOCK.
ALL RIGHT, ENSIGN.
YOU CAN GO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING ME
WHAT THIS IS ALL ABOUT?
I RECEIVE ORDERS
TO PROCEED HERE.
NO REASON GIVEN.
I'M INFORMED THAT MY MEN
WILL BE REMOVED
TO THE SPACE STATION,
TO A SECURITY HOLDING AREA.
I THINK I'M ENTITLED
TO AN EXPLANATION.
YOU'VE HAD A SINGULAR HONOR
CONFERRED ON YOU, JIM.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
THE FOX IN THE HUNT.
WHAT'S THAT?
WAR GAMES.
I'LL BE COMMANDING
THE ATTACK FORCE AGAINST YOU.
AN ENTIRE ATTACK FORCE
AGAINST MY SHIP?
HAVE YOU HEARD
OF THE M-5 MULTITRONIC UNIT?
THAT'S DR. RICHARD DAYSTROM'S
DEVICE, ISN'T IT?
TELL ME ABOUT THAT.
THE MOST AMBITIOUS
COMPUTER COMPLEX EVER CREATED.
ITS PURPOSE IS TO CORRELATE
ALL COMPUTER ACTIVITY
ABOARD A STARSHIP,
TO PROVIDE THE ULTIMATE
IN VESSEL OPERATION AND CONTROL.
HOW DO YOU KNOW SO MUCH
ABOUT IT, COMMANDER?
I HOLD AN A-7
COMPUTER EXPERT CLASSIFICATION,
COMMODORE.
I'M WELL ACQUAINTED
WITH DR. DAYSTROM'S THEORIES
AND DISCOVERIES.
THE BASIC DESIGN
OF ALL OUR SHIP'S COMPUTERS
ARE DR. DAYSTROM'S.
BUT WHAT HAS ALL THIS GOT TO DO
WITH THE ENTERPRISE, COMMODORE?
YOU'VE BEEN CHOSEN
TO TEST THE M-5, JIM.
THERE'LL BE A SERIES
OF ROUTINE RESEARCH
AND CONTACT PROBLEMS
FOR THE M-5 TO SOLVE,
PLUS NAVIGATIONAL MANEUVERS
AND THE WAR GAMES PROBLEM.
NOW, IF THE M-5 WORKS
UNDER ACTUAL CONDITIONS,
AS WELL AS IT HAS
UNDER SIMULATED TESTS,
IT WILL MEAN A REVOLUTION
IN SPACE TECHNOLOGY
AS GREAT AS WARP DRIVE.
WHEN YOUR CREW HAS BEEN REMOVED,
THE SHIP'S ENGINEERING SECTION
WILL BE MODIFIED
TO CONTAIN THE COMPUTER.
WHY REMOVE MY CREW?
THEY'RE NOT NEEDED.
HOW MUCH SECURITY
DOES THIS GADGET REQUIRE?
NONE.
DR. DAYSTROM WILL SEE
TO THE INSTALLATION HIMSELF,
AND HE'LL SUPERVISE THE TESTS.
WHEN HE'S READY
YOU'LL RECEIVE YOUR ORDERS
AND PROCEED ON THE MISSION
WITH A CREW OF 20.
TWENTY?
I CAN'T RUN A STARSHIP
WITH 20 CREW.
THE M-5 CAN.
AND WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
YOU GOT A GREAT JOB, JIM.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS SIT BACK
AND LET THE MACHINE DO THE WORK.
SPACE, THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION:
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 4729.4.
THE M-5 COMPUTER
HAS BEEN INSTALLED
ONBOARD SHIP AND WE HAVE LEFT
THE SPACE STATION
FOR TEST MANEUVERS.
I DON'T LIKE IT, JIM.
A VESSEL THIS SIZE CANNOT BE RUN
BY ONE COMPUTER.
THEY'RE ATTEMPTING TO PROVE
THAT IT CAN RUN THIS SHIP
MORE EFFICIENTLY THAN MAN.
MAYBE YOU'RE TRYING
TO PROVE THAT, SPOCK,
BUT DON'T COUNT ME IN ON IT.
THE MOST UNFORTUNATE LACK
IN CURRENT COMPUTER PROGRAMMING
IS THAT THERE
IS NOTHING AVAILABLE
TO IMMEDIATELY REPLACE
THE STARSHIP SURGEON.
VERY FUNNY.
IF IT COULD, THEY WOULDN'T HAVE
TO REPLACE ME.
I'D RESIGN
BECAUSE EVERYBODY ELSE ABOARD
WOULD BE NOTHING
BUT CIRCUITS AND MEMORY BANKS.
YOU KNOW THE TYPE, SPOCK.
JIM, YOU HAVEN'T HAD MUCH
TO SAY ABOUT THIS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO SAY?
M-5. IT'S AN HONOR,
THEY TELL ME.
WELL, I'M HONORED.
WHERE IS HE?
SCOTTY, WHERE'S DR. DAYSTROM?
WELL, HE WAS HERE.
DOCTOR?
YES?
AH, YOU'D BE CAPTAIN KIRK.
YES, DR. DAYSTROM.
THIS IS MY FIRST OFFICER,
MR. SPOCK.
I AM HONORED, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE FINISHED
MY TESTS ON THE M-5,
AND IT MUST BE HOOKED
INTO YOUR MAIN POWER PLANTS
IN ORDER TO BE OPERATIVE.
WELL, I ALWAYS DO SO.
YOUR ENGINEER THERE
WOULDN'T ALLOW US
THE POWER NECESSARY
WITHOUT YOUR ORDERS.
MR. SCOTT, HOOK IN
THE MULTITRONIC UNIT
TO THE SHIP'S MAIN POWER BANKS.
AYE AYE, SIR.
MR. ARTHUR.
FASCINATING, DOCTOR.
THIS COMPUTER HAS A POTENTIAL
BEYOND ANYTHING
YOU'VE EVER DONE.
EVEN YOUR BREAKTHROUGH
IN DUOTRONICS
DID NOT HAVE THE PROMISE
OF THIS.
THE M-5 HAS BEEN PERFECTED,
COMMANDER.
ITS POTENTIAL IS A FACT.
FRANKLY, THE ONLY FACT
THAT I'M CONCERNED ABOUT
IS IF THIS THING DOESN'T WORK,
THERE ARE NOT ENOUGH MEN ABOARD
TO RUN THIS SHIP,
AND THAT'S BEGGING FOR TROUBLE.
NOW, WHO IS THIS?
DR. LEONARD McCOY,
SENIOR MEDICAL OFFICER.
I'M SORRY,
BUT THIS IS A SECURITY AREA.
I WOULDN'T WORRY, DOCTOR.
DR. McCOY HAS CLEARANCE
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP.
[ BEEPING ]
IS IT SUPPOSED TO DO THAT?
IF I CAN BE OF ASSISTANCE,
DOCTOR?
NO, NO, NO, THANK YOU.
I CAN MANAGE.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG,
CAPTAIN,
JUST A FEW MINOR
SETTLING IN ADJUSTMENTS TO MAKE.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
ALL IS IN ORDER NOW.
I'M CURIOUS, DOCTOR,
WHY IS IT CALLED M-5
AND NOT M-1?
WELL, YOU SEE,
THE MULTITRONIC UNITS
ONE THROUGH FOUR
WERE NOT ENTIRELY SUCCESSFUL.
THIS ONE IS.
M-5 IS READY TO TAKE CONTROL
OF THE SHIP.
TOTAL CONTROL?
THAT IS WHAT IT WAS
DESIGNED FOR, CAPTAIN.
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS
MEN MUST DO TO REMAIN MEN.
YOUR COMPUTER
WOULD TAKE THAT AWAY.
THERE ARE OTHER THINGS
A MAN LIKE YOU MIGHT DO,
OR PERHAPS YOU OBJECT
TO THE POSSIBLE LOSS
OF THE PRESTIGE
AND THE CEREMONY
ACCORDED A STARSHIP CAPTAIN.
THE COMPUTER CAN DO YOUR JOB
AND WITHOUT ALL THAT.
YOU'LL HAVE TO PROVE
THAT TO ME, DOCTOR.
THAT IS WHAT WE'RE HERE FOR,
ISN'T IT, CAPTAIN?
DID YOU SEE THE LOVE LIGHT
IN SPOCK'S EYES?
THE RIGHT COMPUTER
FINALLY CAME ALONG.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, JIM?
I THINK THAT THING IS WRONG,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY.
WELL, I THINK IT'S WRONG, TOO,
REPLACING MEN
WITH MINDLESS MACHINES.
MM-MM, I DON'T MEAN THAT.
I'M GETTING A RED ALERT
RIGHT HERE.
THAT THING IS DANGEROUS.
I FEEL--
ONLY A FOOL WOULD STAND
IN THE WAY OF PROGRESS,
IF THIS IS PROGRESS.
YOU HAVE
MY PSYCHOLOGICAL PROFILES.
AM I AFRAID OF LOSING MY JOB
TO THAT COMPUTER?
JIM, WE'VE ALL SEEN THE ADVANCES
OF MECHANIZATION.
AFTER ALL, DAYSTROM DID DESIGN
THE COMPUTER TO RUN THIS SHIP.
UNDER HUMAN CONTROL.
WE'RE ALL SORRY
FOR THE OTHER GUY
WHEN HE LOSES HIS JOB
TO A MACHINE.
BUT WHEN IT COMES TO YOUR JOB,
THAT'S DIFFERENT,
AND IT ALWAYS WILL BE DIFFERENT.
AM I AFRAID OF LOSING COMMAND
TO A COMPUTER?
DAYSTROM WAS RIGHT.
I CAN DO A LOT OF OTHER THINGS.
AM I AFRAID OF LOSING
THE PRESTIGE AND THE POWER
THAT GOES WITH BEING
A STARSHIP CAPTAIN?
IS THAT WHY I'M FIGHTING?
AM I THAT PETTY?
JIM, IF YOU HAVE THE AWARENESS
TO ASK YOURSELF THAT QUESTION,
YOU DON'T NEED ME TO ANSWER IT
FOR YOU.
WHY DON'T YOU ASK JAMES T. KIRK?
HE'S A PRETTY HONEST GUY.
THE M-5 COMPUTER
IS NOW DISENGAGED.
WE'RE COMING BACK
ON OUR ORIGINAL COURSE, CAPTAIN.
THE M-5 HAS PERFORMED
ADMIRABLY SO FAR.
ALL IT'S DONE IS MAKE
THE REQUIRED COURSE CHANGES
AND A FEW SIMPLE TURNS.
MR. SULU AND MR. CHEKOV
COULD HAVE DONE THAT
WITH THEIR EYES CLOSED.
YES.
BUT YOU SEE, THE IDEA
IS THEY DIDN'T HAVE TO DO IT.
AND YOU FIND
IT WON'T BE NECESSARY
FOR YOU TO REGAIN CONTROL
OF THE UNIT
AFTER IT'S COMPLETED
EACH MANEUVER.
MY ORDERS ARE SUBJECT
TO MY INTERPRETATION
AS TO HOW LONG
THE M-5 IS IN CONTROL,
AND I'LL RUN THE SHIP
IN MY OWN WAY
IF YOU DON'T MIND, DR. DAYSTROM.
CAPTAIN, I AM FORCED
TO AGREE WITH DR. DAYSTROM.
WITH THE COURSE INFORMATION
PLOTTED INTO IT,
HIS COMPUTER
COULD HAVE BROUGHT US HERE
AS EASILY AS THE NAVIGATOR.
IN FACT, IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
A FURTHER DEMONSTRATION
OF M-5's CAPABILITY.
YOU SEEM TO ENJOY TRUSTING
YOURSELF TO THE COMPUTER,
MR. SPOCK.
ENJOY, CAPTAIN?
NO.
I'M MERELY GRATIFIED TO SEE
DR. DAYSTOM'S NEW UNIT
EXECUTE EVERYTHING
REQUIRED OF IT
IN SUCH A HIGHLY
EFFICIENT MANNER.
M-5 IS ANOTHER DISTINGUISHED
TRIUMPH FOR HIS CAREER.
APPROACHING ALPHA CARINAE II.
ETA, FIVE MINUTES.
CAPTAIN, YOUR ORDERS
AT THIS POINT ARE NOT OPEN
TO INTERPRETATION.
YOU MUST COMMIT THE M-5
TO HANDLE ITS APPROACH,
THE ORBIT,
AND THEN TO ANALYZE DATA
REGARDING LANDING PARTY
RECOMMENDATIONS.
IF YOU DON'T MIND, I'LL MAKE
MY OWN RECOMMENDATIONS.
WELL, IF YOU FEEL
YOU NEED THE EXERCISE,
GO ON, CAPTAIN.
M-5 IS COMMITTED.
STANDARD ORBIT, MR. SULU.
CAPTAIN, THE M-5
HAS CALCULATED THAT.
THE ORBIT IS ALREADY PLOTTED.
OH, YES.
STANDARD ORBIT ACHIEVED,
CAPTAIN.
REPORT, MR. SPOCK.
THE PLANET IS CLASS M, CAPTAIN.
OXYGEN-NITROGEN ATMOSPHERE
SUITABLE FOR HUMAN LIFE SUPPORT.
TWO MAJOR LAND MASSES,
A NUMBER OF ISLANDS,
LIFE FORM READINGS.
CAPTAIN, POWER SHUTDOWNS
ON DECK FOUR--
LIGHTS, ENVIRONMENTAL CONTROL.
CHECK IT OUT, SCOTTY.
M-5's READOUT, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
MY RECOMMENDATIONS
ARE AS FOLLOWS:
WE SEND DOWN
GENERAL SURVEY PARTY,
AVOIDING CONTACT
OF ALL INTELLIGENT LIFE
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
THE SURVEY PARTY
WILL CONSIST OF MYSELF,
DR. McCOY,
ASTROBIOLOGIST PHILLIPS,
GEOLOGIST RAWLINS
AND SCIENCE OFFICER SPOCK.
PLAY M-5's RECOMMENDATIONS,
WON'T YOU, MR. SPOCK?
[ BEEPING ]
M-5 readout:
PLANET Alpha Carinae II,
Class M.
Atmosphere: Oxygen, nitrogen.
[ BEEPING ]
POWER'S GONE OFF ON DECK FIVE.
Categorization
of life form readings recorded.
Recommendation
for general survey party:
Science Officer Spock,
Astrobiologist Phillips,
Geologist Carstairs.
WELL, THE ONLY DIFFERENCE
IN REPORTS AND RECOMMENDATIONS
IS THE LANDING PARTY PERSONNEL.
THAT'S ONLY A MATTER
OF JUDGMENT.
JUDGMENT, CAPTAIN?
CAPTAIN,
THE COMPUTER DOES NOT JUDGE.
IT MAKES LOGICAL SELECTIONS.
WHY PICK CARSTAIRS
INSTEAD OF RAWLINS?
CARSTAIRS IS AN ENSIGN,
NO EXPERIENCE.
THIS IS HIS FIRST TOUR OF DUTY.
RAWLINS IS CHIEF GEOLOGIST.
AREN'T YOU REALLY
MORE INTERESTED
IN WHY M-5 DID NOT SELECT YOU
AND DR. McCOY?
WELL, LET'S FIND OUT ANYWAY.
M-5, TIE IN.
M-5.
EXPLANATION FOR LANDING
PARTY RECOMMENDATION.
General survey party requires
direction of science officer.
Astrobiologist Phillips
has surveyed 29
biologically similar planets.
Geologist Carstairs served
on merchant marine freighters
in this area, once visited
planet on geology survey
for a mining company.
WHY WERE THE CAPTAIN
AND THE CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER
NOT INCLUDED IN RECOMMENDATION?
NON-ESSENTIAL PERSONNEL.
CAPTAIN, I'VE LOCATED THE SOURCE
OF THE POWER SHUTDOWNS.
IT'S THE M-5 UNIT, SIR.
THAT THING'S TURNING OFF SYSTEMS
ALL OVER THE SHIP.
HAVE YOU LOCATED
THE MALFUNCTION, DOCTOR?
AS I SUSPECTED,
IT IS NOT A MALFUNCTION.
M-5 WAS MERELY
SHUTTING DOWN POWER
TO AREAS OF THE SHIP
THAT DO NOT REQUIRE IT.
DECKS FOUR AND SIX
ARE LIVING QUARTERS,
ARE THEY NOT?
YES, THAT'S CORRECT.
AND CURRENTLY UNOCCUPIED.
I AM NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THESE INSTRUMENTS, DOCTOR.
YOU ARE USING AN ENTIRELY
NEW TYPE OF CONTROL MECHANISM.
HOWEVER, IT APPEARS TO ME
THIS UNIT
IS DRAWING MORE POWER
THAN BEFORE.
QUITE RIGHT.
AS THE UNIT IS CALLED UPON
TO DO MORE WORK,
IT PULLS MORE POWER TO ENABLE IT
TO DO WHAT IS REQUIRED OF IT,
JUST AS THE HUMAN BODY
DRAWS MORE ENERGY
TO RUN AND TO STAND STILL.
DOCTOR, THIS UNIT
IS NOT A HUMAN BODY.
THE COMPUTER
CAN PROCESS INFORMATION,
BUT ONLY THE INFORMATION
WHICH IS PUT INTO IT.
GRANTED IT CAN WORK A THOUSAND--
A MILLION TIMES FASTER
THAN THE HUMAN BRAIN,
BUT IT CAN'T MAKE
A VALUE JUDGMENT.
IT HAS NO INTUITION.
IT CAN'T THINK.
CAN'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
THE MULTITRONIC UNIT
IS A REVOLUTION
IN COMPUTER SCIENCE.
I DESIGNED
THE DUOTRONIC ELEMENTS
USED IN YOUR SHIP RIGHT NOW,
AND I KNOW
THEY ARE AS ARCHAIC AS DINOSAURS
COMPARED TO THE M-5.
A WHOLE NEW APPROACH.
[ WHISTLING ]
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT?
Sensors are picking up a vessel
paralleling our course,
as yet unidentified.
BE RIGHT UP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE, BONES?
WELL, ALL THE SICK BAY SYSTEMS
ARE SHUTDOWN
UNTIL SUCH TIME AS THE M-5
HAS INFORMED THERE ARE PATIENTS
TO BE CARED FOR.
CAPTAIN, SENSORS REPORT
TWO CONTACTS NOW--
ONE ON THE PORT BOW,
ONE ON THE STERN.
DISTANCE, 200,000 KILOMETERS
AND CLOSING.
IDENTIFICATION?
CAPTAIN, THE M-5 UNIT HAS
ALREADY IDENTIFIED THE VESSELS
AS FEDERATION STARSHIPS
EXCALIBUR AND LEXINGTON.
WE'RE NOT SCHEDULED
FOR WAR GAMES IN THIS AREA.
THIS MAY BE A SURPRISE ATTACK
AS A PROBLEM FOR THE M-5.
PRIORITY MESSAGE COMING IN, SIR.
PUT IT ON AUDIO.
Enterprise
from Commodore Wesley
aboard the USS Lexington.
This is an unscheduled
M-5 drill.
Repeat, this is an M-5 drill.
Enterprise,
acknowledge on this frequency.
ACKNOWLEDGE, LIEUTENANT.
M-5 HAS ACKNOWLEDGED FOR US,
SIR.
THEN GO TO RED ALERT.
AYE, SIR.
[ ALARM ]
CAPTAIN, M-5 HAS ALREADY--
HAS ALREADY SOUNDED
THE RED ALERT.
ALL RIGHT.
MR. SULU, PHASERS 1/100TH POWER.
NO DAMAGE POTENTIAL,
JUST ENOUGH TO NUDGE THEM.
PHASERS 1/100TH POWER, SIR.
PHASER HIT
ON PORT DEFLECTOR FOUR, CAPTAIN.
SPEED INCREASING TO WARP THREE.
TURNING NOW TO 112 MARK 5.
PHASERS LOCKING ON TARGET, SIR.
ENEMY VESSEL CLOSING WITH US.
MAIN PHASERS FIRING.
A HIT, SIR.
TWO MORE.
CHANGING COURSE TO 28 MARK 42.
PHASERS FIRING AGAIN.
TURNING TO 113 MARK 5.
WARP FOUR SPEED.
FIRING AGAIN.
ATTACKING VESSELS
ARE MOVING OFF.
MOVING BACK TO ORIGINAL COURSE
AND SPEED.
REPORT ON DAMAGE SUSTAINED
IN MOCK ATTACK.
MINOR HIT
ON DEFLECTOR SCREEN FOUR.
NO APPRECIABLE DAMAGE.
RATHER IMPRESSIVE DISPLAY
FOR A MACHINE,
WOULDN'T YOU SAY, CAPTAIN?
EVALUATION OF M-5 PERFORMANCE.
IT'LL BE NECESSARY FOR THE LOG.
THE SHIP REACTED MORE RAPIDLY
THAN HUMAN CONTROL
COULD'VE MANEUVERED IT.
TACTICS, DEPLOYMENT OF WEAPONS
ALL INDICATE
AN IMMENSE SOPHISTICATION
IN COMPUTER CONTROL.
MACHINE OVER MAN, SPOCK?
IT WAS IMPRESSIVE.
IT MIGHT EVEN BE PRACTICAL.
PRACTICAL, CAPTAIN?
PERHAPS, BUT NOT DESIRABLE.
COMPUTERS MAKE EXCELLENT
AND EFFICIENT SERVANTS,
BUT I HAVE NO WISH
TO SERVE UNDER THEM.
CAPTAIN, A STARSHIP
ALSO RUNS ON LOYALTY
TO ONE MAN, AND NOTHING
CAN REPLACE IT OR HIM.
CAPTAIN, MESSAGE NOW COMING IN
FROM COMMODORE WESLEY.
PUT IT ON VISUAL.
USS ENTERPRISE FROM STARSHIPS
LEXINGTON AND EXCALIBUR.
BOTH SHIPS REPORT SIMULATED HITS
IN SUFFICIENT QUANTITY
AND LOCATION TO JUSTIFY
AWARDING THE SURPRISE ENGAGEMENT
TO ENTERPRISE.
SECURE FROM GENERAL QUARTERS.
[ BEEPING ]
OUR COMPLIMENTS TO THE M-5 UNIT
AND REGARDS TO CAPTAIN DUNSEL.
WESLEY OUT.
DUNSEL?
WHO THE BLAZE
IS THIS CAPTAIN DUNSEL?
WHAT DOES IT MEAN, JIM?
SPOCK?
WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
DUNSEL, DOCTOR, IS THE TERM
USED BY A MIDSHIPMAN
AT STARFLEET ACADEMY.
IT REFERS TO A PART
WHICH SERVES NO USEFUL PURPOSE.
[ BEEPING ]
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN EATING, BONES.
THIS ISN'T CHICKEN SOUP.
I MAY BE JUST THE SHIP'S DOCTOR,
BUT I MAKE A FINAGLE'S FOLLY
THAT'S KNOWN FROM HERE TO ORION.
I STRONGLY PRESCRIBE IT, JIM.
I HAVE NEVER FELT THIS WAY
BEFORE,
AT ODDS WITH THE SHIP.
I SAT THERE
AND WATCHED MY SHIP PERFORM
FOR A MASS OF CIRCUITS
AND RELAYS
AND FELT USELESS, UNNEEDED.
TO CAPTAIN DUNSEL.
TO JAMES T. KIRK,
CAPTAIN OF THE ENTERPRISE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
THAT'S ONE OF YOUR
BETTER PRESCRIPTIONS.
SIMPLE, BUT EFFECTIVE.
DO YOU KNOW THE ONE,
"ALL I ASK IS A TALL SHIP?"
IT'S A LINE FROM A POEM,
A VERY OLD POEM, ISN'T IT?
TWENTIETH CENTURY EARTH.
"ALL I ASK IS A TALL SHIP
AND A STAR TO STEER HER BY."
YOU COULD FEEL THE WIND
AT YOUR BACK IN THOSE DAYS,
THE SOUNDS OF THE SEA
BENEATH YOU.
AND EVEN IF YOU TAKE AWAY
THE WIND AND THE WATER,
IT'S STILL THE SAME.
THE SHIP IS YOURS.
YOU CAN FEEL HER, AND THE STARS
ARE STILL THERE, BONES.
[ WHISTLING ]
Captain Kirk to the bridge,
please.
Captain Kirk.
KIRK HERE.
Another contact, Captain,
a large slow-moving vessel,
unidentified.
This is not a drill.
ON MY WAY.
CAPTAIN, THERE'S NO RESPONSE
TO ANY OF OUR SIGNALS,
BUT M-5 HAS GIVEN US
AN ORDER RELAY.
M-5 HAS IDENTIFIED HER, CAPTAIN.
THE WODEN, LISTED
IN STARFLEET REGISTRY
AS AN OLD-STYLE ORE FREIGHTER
CONVERTED TO AUTOMATION,
NO CREW.
COMING INTO VISUAL RANGE.
[ BEEPING ]
CAPTAIN, DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
JUST CAME ON.
SPEED INCREASING TO WARP THREE,
CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT,
GET DAYSTROM UP HERE.
DISENGAGING M-5 UNIT.
CUT SPEED TO WARP ONE,
NAVIGATOR.
GO TO COURSE 113, MARK 7.
I WANT THAT SHIP
GIVEN A WIDE BERTH.
SHE WON'T RESPOND, SIR.
SHE'S MAINTAINING COURSE.
THAT'S THE WRONG COURSE, SIR.
JIM.
SCOTTY, REVERSE ENGINE.
SLOW US DOWN.
REVERSE THRUST WILL NOT ENGAGE,
SIR.
MANUAL OVERRIDE
ISN'T WORKING EITHER.
NO AFFECT ON ANY OF THE M-5
CONTROLS, CAPTAIN.
[ ALARM ]
FANTASTIC MACHINE, THE M-5.
NO OFF SWITCH.
CAPTAIN, WHAT IS IT?
THESE CONTROLS ARE LOCKED.
WE CAN'T DISENGAGE THE COMPUTER.
CAPTAIN, PHOTON TORPEDOES
LOCKING ON TARGET.
FULL POWER.
I ALREADY TRIED, SIR.
DAYSTROM, RELEASE
THE COMPUTER CONTROLS.
RETURNING TO ORIGINAL COURSE
AND SPEED.
ALL SYSTEMS REPORT NORMAL,
CAPTAIN.
NORMAL?
THAT THING IS TRYING TO TELL US
NOTHING HAS HAPPENED.
DISENGAGE THIS COMPUTER NOW.
THERE APPEARS TO BE SOME DEFECT
IN THE CONTROL PANEL.
THERE CERTAINLY DOES.
YOUR BRILLIANT YOUNG COMPUTER
JUST DESTROYED AN ORE FREIGHTER.
IN FACT, IT WENT OUT OF ITS WAY
TO DESTROY AN ORE FREIGHTER.
FORTUNATELY,
IT WAS ONLY A ROBOT SHIP.
- ONLY A ROBOT?
- BUT IT SHOULDN'T HAVE
DESTROYED ANYTHING.
THERE MIGHT JUST AS EASILY HAVE
BEEN A CREW ABOARD THAT SHIP.
IN WHICH CASE, YOU WOULD BE
GUILTY OF MURDER.
BONES. DISENGAGE THE COMPUTER.
LIEUTENANT,
CONTACT STARFLEET COMMAND.
TELL THEM WE ARE BREAKING OFF
M-5 TESTS
AND RETURNING
TO THE SPACE STATION.
COME ALONG, DR. DAYSTROM.
M-5 IS OUT OF A JOB.
ALL RIGHT, DAYSTROM.
LET'S TURN THIS THING OFF.
FORCE FIELD?
IT'S NOT MY DOING, KIRK.
I WOULD SAY, CAPTAIN,
THAT M-5 IS NOT ONLY CAPABLE
OF TAKING CARE OF THE SHIP,
BUT IT'S ALSO CAPABLE
OF TAKING CARE OF ITSELF.
YOU MEAN IT'S NOT GONNA LET
ANY OF US TURN IT OFF.
CAPTAIN'S LOG: STARDATE 4731.3.
THE M-5 MULTITRONIC UNIT
HAS TAKEN OVER TOTAL CONTROL
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR,
YOU BUILT THIS THING,
HOW DO YOU PROPOSE
TO TURN IT OFF?
THIS ENTIRE EXERCISE
IS A TRIAL FOR M-5,
A SHAKEDOWN.
WE MUST EXPECT
A FEW MINOR DIFFICULTIES,
BUT I ASSURE YOU
IT CAN BE CORRECTED.
CORRECTED AFTER YOU RELEASE
CONTROL OF MY SHIP.
I CAN'T.
CAPTAIN, I SUGGEST
WE DISCONNECT IT AT THE SOURCE.
GIVE ME A FEW MOMENTS WITH IT.
NO. STAY HERE.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY, TURN IT OFF.
THAT WASN'T A MINOR DIFFICULTY.
THAT WASN'T A ROBOT.
THAT THING MURDERED
ONE OF MY CREWMEN
AND NOW YOU'RE TELLING ME
YOU CAN'T TURN IT OFF?
IT WASN'T A DELIBERATE ACT.
M-5's ANALYSIS TOLD IT
IT NEEDED A NEW POWER SOURCE.
THE ENSIGN SIMPLY GOT
IN THE WAY, I THINK.
AND HOW LONG WILL IT BE
BEFORE ALL OF US
SIMPLY GET IN THE WAY?
M-5 APPEARS TO BE DRAWING POWER
DIRECTLY FROM THE WARP ENGINES,
TAPPING THE MATTER-ANTIMATTER
RESERVES.
SO NOW IT HAS FACTUALLY
UNLIMITED POWER.
CAPTAIN, WHAT DO WE DO?
SPOCK, SCOTTY, COME WITH ME.
REPORT, SPOCK.
THE MULTITRONIC UNIT
IS DRAWING MORE AND MORE POWER
DIRECTLY FROM THE WARP ENGINES.
THE COMPUTER NOW CONTROLS
ALL HELM NAVIGATION
AND ENGINEERING FUNCTIONS.
AND COMMUNICATIONS
AND FIRING CONTROL.
WE'LL REACH THE RENDEZVOUS POINT
FOR THE WAR GAMES
WITHIN AN HOUR.
WE MUST REGAIN CONTROL
OF THE SHIP BY THEN.
THERE IS ONE POSSIBILITY.
THE AUTOMATIC HELM NAVIGATION
CIRCUIT RELAYS
MIGHT BE DISRUPTED
FROM ENGINEERING LEVEL THREE.
SCOTTY?
AYE, I CAN TAKE THEM OUT
AND CUT IN THE MANUAL OVERRIDE
FROM THERE.
HOW LONG?
IF MR. SPOCK HELPS ME,
MAYBE AN HOUR.
MAKE IT LESS.
WHY NOT GET THE MAN RESPONSIBLE
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
WHERE IS DAYSTROM?
HE'S WITH THE M-5 UNIT
WATCHING IT.
I THINK IT SURPRISED EVEN HIM.
MOST ILLOGICAL.
OF ALL PEOPLE,
HE SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
HOW THE COMPUTER WOULD PERFORM.
OF COURSE, THE M-5 ITSELF
HAS NOT BEHAVED LOGICALLY.
PLEASE, SPOCK, DO ME A FAVOR
AND DON'T SAY IT'S FASCINATING.
NO, BUT IT IS INTERESTING.
AYE. THAT'S DONE IT, MR. SPOCK.
GOOD.
HAVE YOU FOUND THE SOLUTION,
A WAY TO SHUT THAT THING OFF?
YOU DON'T SHUT A CHILD OFF
WHEN IT MAKES A MISTAKE.
M-5 IS GROWING, LEARNING.
LEARNING TO KILL.
TO DEFEND ITSELF.
IT'S QUITE A DIFFERENT THING.
WHEN A CHILD IS TAUGHT,
IT'S PROGRAMMED
TO ITS SIMPLE INSTRUCTIONS.
AND AT SOME POINT,
IF ITS MIND DEVELOPS PROPERLY,
IT EXCEEDS THE SUM
OF WHAT IT WAS TAUGHT,
THINKS INDEPENDENTLY.
THAT THING IS A DANGER
TO ALL OF US.
NOW, FIND SOME WAY
TO SHUT IT OFF.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
YOU'RE FRIGHTENED
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND IT.
I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU.
I'M GOING TO SHOW ALL OF YOU.
IT TAKES 430 PEOPLE
TO MAN A STARSHIP.
WITH THIS
YOU DON'T NEED ANYONE.
ONE MACHINE CAN DO
ALL THOSE THINGS
THEY SEND MEN OUT TO DO NOW.
MEN NO LONGER NEED DIE IN SPACE
OR ON SOME ALIEN WORLD.
MEN CAN LIVE AND GO ON
TO ACHIEVE GREATER THINGS
THAN FACT FINDING
AND DYING FOR GALACTIC SPACE.
IT IS NEITHER OURS TO GIVE
OR TO TAKE.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND.
WE DON'T WANT TO DESTROY LIFE,
WE WANT TO SAVE IT.
BIOGRAPHICAL TAPE
OF RICHARD DAYSTROM.
DID YOU FIND OUT ANYTHING?
NOT MUCH, ASIDE FROM THE FACT
HE'S A GENIUS.
GENIUS IS AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
AT THE AGE OF 24, HE MADE
THE DUOTRONIC BREAKTHROUGH
THAT WON HIM A NOBEL
AND ZEE-MAGNES PRIZES.
IN HIS EARLY 20s, JIM.
THAT'S OVER A QUARTER
OF A CENTURY AGO.
ISN'T THAT ENOUGH
FOR ONE LIFETIME?
MAYBE THAT'S THE TROUBLE.
WHERE DO YOU GO FROM UP?
YOU PUBLISH YOUR ARTICLES,
YOU GIVE LECTURES,
AND YOU SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE
TRYING TO RECAPTURE PAST GLORY.
ALL RIGHT, IT'S DIFFICULT.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
THE M-1 THROUGH M-4, REMEMBER?
NOT ENTIRELY SUCCESSFUL.
THAT'S THE WAY DAYSTROM PUT IT.
A GENIUS DOESN'T WORK
ON THE ASSEMBLY LINE BASIS.
DID EINSTEIN, KAZANGA
OR SITAR OF VULCAN PRODUCE
NEW AND REVOLUTIONARY THEORIES
ON A REGULAR SCHEDULE?
YOU CAN'T SIMPLY SAY,
"TODAY, I WILL BE BRILLIANT."
NO MATTER HOW LONG IT TOOK,
HE CAME OUT WITH MULTITRONICS,
THE M-5.
RIGHT.
THE GOVERNMENT BOUGHT IT,
THEN DAYSTROM HAD
TO MAKE IT WORK, AND HE DID.
BUT ACCORDING TO SPOCK,
IT WORKS ILLOGICALLY.
AND HE WON'T LET SPOCK NEAR IT.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING,
THAT HE'S TAMPERING WITH IT,
THAT HE'S MAKING IT
ACT THAT WAY?
WHY?
JIM, IF A MAN HAD A CHILD
WHO'D GONE ANTISOCIAL--
KILLED, PERHAPS--
HE'D STILL TEND TO PROTECT
THAT CHILD.
NOW HE'S GOT YOU TALKING
ABOUT THAT MACHINE
LIKE A PERSONALITY.
I'M AFRAID THAT'S THE WAY
HE THINKS ABOUT IT.
[ WHISTLING ]
Spock to Captain Kirk.
KIRK HERE.
We are ready, Captain.
GOOD. GET DAYSTROM.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY.
LET'S GO.
WHAT IS IT, CAPTAIN?
WE'D BETTER FIND OUT, DOCTOR.
SPOCK?
MR. SCOTT IS READY TO APPLY
THE CIRCUIT DISRUPTER, CAPTAIN.
AS HE DOES SO,
I SHALL TRIP THE MANUAL OVERRIDE
INTO CONTROL.
GOOD.
GO AHEAD.
NO! NO, NO, NO!
YOU CAN'T TAKE CONTROL
FROM THE M-5!
DR. DAYSTROM,
WE'RE GONNA DO OUR VERY BEST.
YOU CAN'T DO IT!
NOW, LET ME HAVE IT FOR A WHILE!
LET ME WORK WITH IT FOR A WHILE,
PLEASE! PLEASE!
COME ON.
THAT'S IT, MR. SPOCK.
PLEASE!
MANUAL OVERRIDE IS IN CONTROL,
CAPTAIN.
BRIDGE, THIS IS KIRK. SULU?
Lieutenant Sulu here, sir.
WE'VE GOT HELM
AND NAVIGATIONAL CONTROL.
TURN US ABOUT.
HAVE MR. CHEKOV PLOT A COURSE
BACK TO THE SPACE STATION.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
YOU HEARD HIM?
I'VE BEEN UPDATING THAT COURSE
FOR HOURS.
Helm to Captain Kirk.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, HELM DOESN'T RESPOND.
NAVIGATIONAL CONTROLS
STILL LOCKED IN BY M-5.
MR. CHEKOV?
Chekov here, sir.
GO TO THE ENGINEERING STATION.
Examine the H-279 elements,
also the G-95 systems.
[ BEEPING ]
SIR, G-95 SYSTEM APPEARS DEAD.
ALL INDICATORS ARE DARK.
THANK YOU, ENSIGN.
IT APPEARS, CAPTAIN,
WE'VE BEEN DOING
WHAT USED TO BE CALLED
PURSUING A WILD GOOSE.
M-5 HAS REROUTED HELM
AND NAVIGATIONAL CONTROLS,
BYPASSING THIS PRIMARY SYSTEM.
BUT IT WAS ACTIVE.
I'D STAKE ALL I KNOW
THAT IT WAS.
I BELIEVE THAT WHEN M-5
DISCOVERED OUR TAMPERING,
IT REROUTED THE CONTROLS,
LEAVING THIS ONE ACTIVE
BY SIMPLY SENDING THROUGH
AN ELECTRONIC IMPULSE
AT REGULAR INTERVALS.
DECOYED.
IT WANTED US
TO WASTE OUR TIME HERE.
WHILE IT WAS GETTING READY
FOR WHAT, SPOCK?
I DO NOT KNOW.
IT IS NOT PERFORMING
IN A LOGICAL MANNER.
DR. DAYSTROM.
DR. DAYSTROM,
I WANT AN ANSWER RIGHT NOW.
I'M TIRED OF HEARING
ABOUT THE M-5's NEW APPROACH.
WHAT IS IT EXACTLY?
WHAT IS IT?
I DO NOT MEAN TO OFFEND, SIR,
BUT IT BEHAVES
WITH AN ALMOST HUMAN PATTERN.
WELL, DOCTOR?
YES, QUITE RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
YOU SEE, ONE OF THE ARGUMENTS
AGAINST COMPUTERS
CONTROLLING SHIPS
WAS THAT THEY COULDN'T THINK
LIKE MEN.
YOUR NEW APPROACH?
EXACTLY.
I'VE DEVELOPED A METHOD
OF IMPRESSING HUMAN ENGRAMS
UPON THE COMPUTER CIRCUITS.
THE RELAYS ARE NOT UNLIKE
THE SYNAPSE OF THE BRAIN.
M-5 THINKS, CAPTAIN.
[ WHISTLING ]
Captain Kirk, Mr. Spock,
to the bridge, please.
Report to the bridge, please.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT?
SIR, SENSORS ARE PICKING UP
FOUR FEDERATION STARSHIPS.
M-5 IS ALTERING COURSE
TO INTERCEPT.
THE MAIN ATTACK FORCE.
THE WAR GAMES.
BUT M-5 DOESN'T KNOW
IT'S A GAME.
CORRECTION, BONES.
THOSE FOUR SHIPS DON'T KNOW
IT'S M-5's GAME.
AND M-5
IS GOING TO DESTROY THEM.
ENTERPRISE TO U.S.S. LEXINGTON.
COME IN, LEXINGTON.
SIR, I CAN'T RAISE THEM.
M-5 IS STILL BLOCKING
ALL FREQUENCIES
INCLUDING AUTOMATIC DISTRESS.
JUST A MINUTE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING
AUDIO SIGNAL FROM THE LEXINGTON.
PUT IT ON.
Enterprise
from U.S.S. Lexington.
This is an M-5 drill.
Repeat, this is an M-5 drill.
Acknowledge.
CAPTAIN, M-5 IS ACKNOWLEDGING.
DAYSTROM, DOES M-5 UNDERSTAND
THAT THIS IS ONLY A DRILL?
OF COURSE.
IT WAS PROGRAMMED TO UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
THE ORE SHIP
WAS A MISCALCULATION,
AN ACCIDENT.
I DON'T KNOW--
SIR, DEFLECTOR SHIELD
JUST CAME ON.
SPEED INCREASING TO WARP FOUR.
PHASERS LOCKING ON LEAD SHIP,
SIR.
POWER LEVELS AT FULL STRENGTH.
FULL STRENGTH?
THAT THING CUTS LOOSE
AT UNSHIELDED SHIPS, WE'RE IN--
THAT'S NO MISCALCULATION.
ATTACK FORCE CLOSING RAPIDLY,
BREAKING FORMATION,
ATTACKING AT WILL.
PHASERS ARE FIRING, SIR.
[ EXPLOSION ]
HIT ON THE LEXINGTON.
FULL PHASERS.
WHAT THE DEVIL IS KIRK DOING?
[ ALARM ]
DAMAGE REPORT, LIEUTENANT.
HELM, COURSE 164, MARK 3.
TURNING NOW, SIR.
ESTIMATE DAMAGE ON LEXINGTON,
SPOCK.
HIT IN ENGINEERING SECTION,
POSSIBLE DAMAGE
TO HER IMPULSE ENGINES.
SHE'S STILL MANEUVERABLE
ON WARP DRIVE.
WE'RE FIRING AGAIN, SIR.
EXCALIBUR, A DIRECT HIT.
CLOSING ON LEXINGTON AGAIN, SIR.
THE HOOD AND POTEMKIN
ARE MOVING OFF.
PHASERS FIRING, CAPTAIN.
LEXINGTON HIT AGAIN.
THERE'S GOT TO BE A WAY
OF GETTING TO THE M-5.
THERE'S GOT TO BE A WAY.
THERE ISN'T.
IT'S TOTALLY PROTECTED ITSELF.
PROBABLY TRUE, CAPTAIN.
IT WORKS FASTER,
THINKS FASTER THAN WE DO.
IT IS A HUMAN MIND AMPLIFIED
BY THE INSTANTANEOUS RELAYS
POSSIBLE IN A COMPUTER.
CAPTAIN, VISUAL CONTACT
WITH LEXINGTON.
ENTERPRISE TO JIM.
HAVE YOU GONE MAD?
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO PROVE?
BREAK OFF THE ATTACK.
JIM, WE HAVE 53 DEAD HERE,
12 ON THE EXCALIBUR.
NOW, IF YOU CAN HEAR US,
STOP THE ATTACK!
LIEUTENANT.
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I CAN'T OVERRIDE
M-5 INTERFERENCE.
JIM, WHY DON'T YOU ANSWER?
JIM, ANSWER!
COME IN, JIM.
THERE'S YOUR MURDER CHARGE.
DELIBERATE. CALCULATED.
THAT THING IS KILLING MEN
AND WOMEN,
FOUR STARSHIPS,
1,600 MEN AND WOMEN.
IT MISUNDERSTOOD.
Jim, break off your attack.
THE EXCALIBUR
IS MANEUVERING AWAY, SIR.
WE'RE INCREASING SPEED
TO FOLLOW.
[ BEEPING ]
PHASERS LOCKED ON.
DAYSTROM!
[ PHASERS ]
PHASERS FIRING.
I REALLY DON'T KNOW HOW
TO GET TO THE M-5, KIRK.
I REALLY DO NOT KNOW.
DR. DAYSTROM,
YOU IMPRESSED HUMAN ENGRAMS
ON THE M-5 CIRCUITS.
COMING TO NEW COURSE, SIR.
BEARING ON THE POTEMKIN.
[ PHASERS ]
PHASERS FIRED.
A HIT.
WHOSE ENGRAMS?
WHY, MINE, OF COURSE.
OF COURSE.
THEN PERHAPS YOU COULD TALK
TO THE UNIT.
M-5 HAS NO REASON TO BELIEVE
YOU WOULD HARM IT.
THE COMPUTER TIE-IN.
YOU SPOKE TO IT BEFORE.
IT KNOWS YOU.
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING
THE LEXINGTON AGAIN,
TAPPING IN ON THEIR MESSAGE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND, SIR.
[ BEEPING ]
ALL SHIPS DAMAGED
IN UNPROVOKED ATTACK.
EXCALIBUR CAPTAIN HARRIS
AND FIRST OFFICER DEAD.
Many casualties.
We have damage
but are still able to maneuver.
The Enterprise refuses to answer
and is continuing attack.
I STILL HAVE
AN EFFECTIVE BATTLEFORCE.
I BELIEVE THE ONLY WAY
TO STOP THE ENTERPRISE
IS TO DESTROY HER.
REQUEST PERMISSION TO PROCEED.
Wesley,
commanding attack force, out.
THEY CAN'T DO THAT.
THEY'LL DESTROY THE M-5.
YOU CAN SAVE THE M-5
IF YOU TALK TO IT
AND MAKE IT STOP THE ATTACK.
I CAN MAKE IT STOP.
I CREATED IT.
M-5, TIE IN.
M-5.
THIS IS--THIS IS DAYSTROM.
Daystrom acknowledged.
M-5, DO YOU KNOW ME?
Daystrom, Richard,
originator of comptronic
duotronic systems. Born...
STOP. M-5, YOUR ATTACK
ON THE STARSHIPS IS WRONG.
YOU MUST BREAK IT OFF.
I DON'T LIKE THE SOUND OF HIM,
JIM.
YOU BETTER PRAY THAT THE M-5
LISTENS TO THE SOUND.
Programming includes protection
against attack.
Enemy vessels
must be neutralized.
BUT THESE ARE NOT ENEMY VESSELS.
THESE ARE FEDERATION STARSHIPS.
YOU'RE KILLING,
WE'RE KILLING,
MURDERING HUMAN BEINGS,
BEINGS OF OUR OWN KIND.
YOU WERE NOT CREATED
FOR THAT PURPOSE.
YOU'RE MY GREATEST CREATION,
THE UNIT TO SAVE MEN.
YOU MUST NOT DESTROY MEN.
This unit must survive.
SURVIVE, YES.
PROTECT YOURSELF,
BUT NOT MURDER.
YOU MUST NOT DIE.
MEN MUST NOT DIE.
TO KILL IS A BREAKING
OF CIVIL AND MORAL LAWS
WE'VE LIVED BY
FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS.
YOU'VE MURDERED
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE.
WE'VE MURDERED.
HOW CAN WE REPAY THAT?
They attacked this unit.
Programming includes full--
SPOCK?
--freedom to choose
defensive actions
in all attack situations.
THE M-5 IS NOT RESPONDING.
IT'S TALKING TO HIM.
I AM MOST IMPRESSED
WITH THE TECHNOLOGY, CAPTAIN.
DR. DAYSTROM HAS CREATED
A MIRROR IMAGE OF HIS OWN MIND.
My consideration
of all programming
is that we must survive.
WE WILL SURVIVE.
NOTHING CAN HURT YOU.
I GAVE YOU THAT.
YOU ARE GREAT. I AM GREAT.
TWENTY YEARS OF GROPING TO PROVE
THE THINGS I'D DONE BEFORE
WERE NOT ACCIDENTS.
SEMINARS AND LECTURES
TO ROWS OF FOOLS
WHO COULDN'T BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND
MY SYSTEMS.
COLLEAGUES LAUGHING BEHIND
MY BACK AT THE BOY WONDER,
AND BECOMING FAMOUS
BUILDING ON MY WORK,
BUILDING ON MY WORK.
JIM, HE'S ON THE EDGE
OF A NERVOUS BREAKDOWN,
IF NOT INSANITY.
THE M-5 MUST BE DESTROYED.
DESTROY IT, KIRK?
NO. WE'RE INVINCIBLE.
LOOK WHAT WE'VE DONE.
YOUR MIGHTY STARSHIPS, WAR TOYS
TO BE CRUSHED AS WE CHOOSE.
SECURITY, TAKE HIM TO SICK BAY.
FASCINATING.
TAKE CARE OF HIM, DOCTOR.
VITAL STATS.
THE OTHER THREE SHIPS
ARE HOLDING STATION
OUT OF RANGE.
THE EXCALIBUR LOOKS DEAD.
CAPTAIN, LEXINGTON
IS RECEIVING A MESSAGE
FROM STARFLEET.
THEY...
GO ON.
You are authorized
to use all measures available
to destroy the Enterprise.
Acknowledge, Lexington.
Acknowledged. Lexington out.
THEY'VE JUST SIGNED
THEIR OWN DEATH WARRANT.
M-5 WILL KILL THEM TO SURVIVE.
EVERY LIVING THING
WANTS TO SURVIVE, CAPTAIN.
DAYSTROM MUST HAVE IMPRESSED
THAT INSTINCTIVE REACTION
UPON THE COMPUTER.
SUPPOSE IT'S STILL OPEN
TO IMPRESSION,
SUPPOSE IT ABSORBED THE REGRET
DAYSTROM FELT
FOR THE DEATHS IT CAUSED,
THE GUILT.
CAPTAIN, THE SHIPS
ARE COMING WITHIN RANGE AGAIN.
COMMODORE WESLEY
IS A DEDICATED COMMANDER.
I SHOULD REGRET SERVING ABOARD
THE INSTRUMENT OF HIS DEATH.
THE INSTRUMENT OF HIS DEATH
WILL NOT BE THE ENTERPRISE
IF I CAN HELP IT.
M-5, TIE IN.
M-5.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU WILL BE UNDER ATTACK
IN A MOMENT.
Sensors have recorded
approaching ships.
YOU HAVE ALREADY RENDERED
ONE STARSHIP EITHER DEAD
OR HOPELESSLY CRIPPLED.
MANY LIVES WERE LOST.
The ships attacked this unit.
This unit must survive.
WHY?
This unit is the ultimate
achievement
in computer evolution.
It will replace man
so man may achieve.
Man must not risk death in space
or other dangerous occupations.
This unit must survive
so man may be protected.
CAPTAIN, ATTACK FORCE
ALMOST WITHIN PHASER RANGE.
THERE WERE MANY MEN
ABOARD THOSE SHIPS.
THEY WERE MURDERED.
MUST YOU SURVIVE BY MURDER?
This unit cannot murder.
WHY?
Murder is contrary
to the laws of man and God.
BUT YOU HAVE MURDERED.
SCAN THE STARSHIP EXCALIBUR,
WHICH YOU DESTROYED.
IS THERE LIFE ABOARD?
No life.
BECAUSE YOU MURDERED IT.
WHAT IS THE PENALTY FOR MURDER?
Death.
AND HOW WILL YOU PAY
FOR YOUR ACTS OF MURDER?
Must die.
M-5?
SIR, DETECTOR SHIELDS
HAVE DROPPED.
ALL PHASER POWER GONE, SIR.
M-5 IS LEAVING ITSELF OPEN
TO ATTACK.
THE MACHINE
IS COMMITTING SUICIDE
TO ATONE FOR THE SIN OF MURDER.
SCOTTY, SPOCK,
BEFORE IT CHANGES ITS MIND,
GO DOWN TO ENGINEERING
AND PULL OUT EVERY HOOK-UP
THAT MAKES M-5 RUN.
PULL OUT THE PLUG, SPOCK.
LIEUTENANT?
AYE, SIR.
ENTER SHIP'S COMMUNICATIONS.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
IN APPROXIMATELY ONE MINUTE
WE'LL BE ATTACKED
BY FEDERATION STARSHIPS.
THE M-5 NO LONGER CONTROLS
THE SHIP,
BUT THEN NEITHER DO WE
CONTROL IT.
THE M-5 HAS LEFT ITSELF AND US
OPEN FOR DESTRUCTION.
FOR WHATEVER SATISFACTION
WE MAY GET FROM THE KNOWLEDGE,
OUR 19 LIVES
WILL BUY THE SURVIVAL
OF OVER 1,000
OF OUR FELLOW STARSHIP CREWMEN.
PHASERS ARE AT TARGET.
Spock to captain.
KIRK HERE.
FORCE FIELD IS GONE, CAPTAIN.
M-5 IS NEUTRALIZED.
SYSTEMS COMING BACK.
I CAN GIVE YOU POWER
FOR THE SHIELD, SIR.
I NEED COMMUNICATIONS.
WELL, THAT WILL TAKE LONGER.
THEN, CUT POWER.
SIR?
CUT POWER.
KEEP THOSE SHIELDS DOWN.
THE ENTERPRISE LOOKS DEAD.
I'M GONNA TAKE A CHANCE
HE'S NOT JUST LAYING A TRAP.
WESLEY TO ATTACK FORCE.
CAPTAIN?
Break off attack.
Do not fire.
Enterprise has dropped
her shields.
I repeat, hold attack.
Do not fire.
HE'LL HAVE TO BE COMMITTED
TO A TOTAL
REHABILITATION CENTER.
RIGHT NOW HE'S UNDER SEDATION
AND HEAVY RESTRAINTS.
I WOULD SAY HIS MULTITRONIC UNIT
IS IN APPROXIMATELY
THE SAME CONDITION.
THAT'S EXACTLY THE SITUATION
I WAS HOPING FOR.
WHEN I FORCED THE M-5 TO REALIZE
THAT IT HAD COMMITTED MURDER,
DAYSTROM FELT THAT SUCH AN ACT
WAS AN OFFENSE
AGAINST THE LAWS OF GOD AND MAN.
AND THE COMPUTER THAT CARRIED
HIS ENGRAMS ALSO BELIEVED IT.
CAPTAIN, WHY DID YOU FEEL
THE ATTACKING SHIPS
WOULD NOT FIRE
WHEN THEY SAW THE ENTERPRISE
APPARENTLY VULNERABLE?
LOGICALLY,
THAT IS THE SORT OF TRAP
M-5 SHOULD HAVE SET FOR THEM.
I WASN'T SURE.
ANY OTHER COMMANDER WOULD HAVE
SIMPLY FOLLOWED ORDERS
AND DESTROYED IT,
BUT I KNEW BOB WESLEY.
I GAMBLED ON HIS HUMANITY.
BRIDGE.
HIS LOGICAL SELECTION
WAS COMPASSION.
COMPASSION?
THAT'S THE ONE THING
NO MACHINE EVER HAD.
MAYBE IT'S THE ONE THING
THAT KEEPS MEN AHEAD OF THEM.
CARE TO DEBATE THAT, SPOCK?
NO, DOCTOR.
I SIMPLY MAINTAIN THAT COMPUTERS
ARE MORE EFFICIENT
THAN HUMAN BEINGS, NOT BETTER.
BUT TELL ME, WHICH DO YOU PREFER
TO HAVE AROUND?
I PRESUME YOUR QUESTION
IS MEANT TO OFFER ME A CHOICE
BETWEEN MACHINES
AND HUMAN BEINGS,
AND I BELIEVE I HAVE ALREADY
ANSWERED THAT QUESTION.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO MAKE CONVERSATION, SPOCK.
IT WOULD BE MOST INTERESTING
TO IMPRESS YOUR MEMORY ENGRAMS
ON A COMPUTER, DOCTOR.
THE RESULTING
TORRENTIAL FLOOD OF ILLOGIC
WOULD BE MOST ENTERTAINING.
MR. SULU, TAKE US BACK
TO THE SPACE STATION,
AND WARP BACK TO TWO.