NO DOUBT ABOUT IT,
CAPTAIN.
THE SPACE DEBRIS COMES
FROM THE SURVEY VESSEL
S.S. BEAGLE.
MISSING
FOR SIX YEARS,
AND NOW THIS--
JUNK IN SPACE.
PORTIONS OF
THE ANTIMATTER NACELLES,
PERSONAL BELONGINGS...
CAPTAIN, NO SIGNS
OF BODIES WHATSOEVER.
THEN WHATEVER
DESTROYED THE SHIP,
THE CREW WAS ABLE
TO GET OFF SAFELY.
NAVIGATOR, COMPUTE
THE PRESENT DRIFT
OF THE WRECKAGE.
COMPUTED AND ON
THE BOARD, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, ASSUMING THAT
THE WRECKAGE DRIFTED
AT THE SAME SPEED
AND DIRECTION FOR
THE PAST SIX YEARS...
IT WOULD HAVE COME
FROM PLANET 4,
STAR SYSTEM 892,
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
ONLY 1/16 PARSEC AWAY,
CAPTAIN.
WE SHOULD BE THERE
IN SECONDS.
STANDARD ORBIT
AROUND THE PLANET.
THERE MAY BE
SURVIVORS THERE.
S.S. BEAGLE--
SMALL CLASS FOUR
STARDRIVE VESSEL,
CREW OF 47,
COMMANDED BY...
JIM, I BELIEVE
YOU KNEW HIM.
CAPTAIN R.M. MERIK.
YES, AT THE ACADEMY.
HE WAS DROPPED
IN HIS FIFTH YEAR.
HE WENT INTO THE
MERCHANT SERVICE.
COMING UP
ON THE PLANET, CAPTAIN.
PUT IT ON
THE SCREEN.
DEFINITELY
CLASS "M."
SOMEWHAT SIMILAR
TO EARTH.
YES, SIMILAR,
BUT THE LAND MASSES
AND OCEANS
ARE QUITE DIFFERENT,
HOWEVER.
DIFFERENT IN SHAPE
ONLY, CAPTAIN.
THE PROPORTION
OF LAND TO WATER
IS EXACTLY
AS ON OUR EARTH.
DENSITY 5.5,
DIAMETER 7,917
AT THE EQUATOR.
ATMOSPHERE
IS 78% NITROGEN,
21% OXYGEN.
AGAIN,
EXACTLY LIKE EARTH.
EXACTLY IN SOME WAYS,
DIFFERENT IN OTHERS.
I ALSO PICKED UP
INDICATIONS OF LARGE CITIES.
WHAT ERA?
NO SIGN OF ATOMIC POWER
AS YET,
BUT FAR ENOUGH ALONG
FOR RADIO COMMUNICATIONS,
POWER TRANSPORTATION,
AN EXCELLENT ROAD SYSTEM.
CAPTAIN, BOTH AMPLITUDE
AND FREQUENCY MODULATION
BEING USED.
I THINK I CAN PICK UP
SOMETHING VISUAL.
IT'S A NEWS BROADCAST
USING A SYSTEM I THINK
THEY ONCE CALLED VIDEO.
TELEVISION
WAS THE COLLOQUIAL TERM.
PUT IT ON THE SCREEN.
RIGHT.
TODAY POLICE ROUNDED UP
STILL ANOTHER GROUP
OF DISSIDENTS.
AUTHORITIES ARE AS YET
UNABLE TO EXPLAIN
THESE FRESH OUTBREAKS
OF TREASONABLE DISOBEDIENCE
BY WELL-TREATED,
WELL-PROTECTED,
INTELLIGENT SLAVES.
NOW TURNING TO
THE WORLD OF SPORTS
AND BRINGING YOU
THE TAPED RESULTS
OF THE ARENA GAMES
LAST NIGHT.
THE FIRST HEAT
INVOLVED AMATEURS.
A PAIR OF PETTY THIEVES
FROM THE CITY PRISON,
CONDUCTED, HOWEVER,
WITH TRADITIONAL WEAPONS...
[CROWD JEERING]
WORTHY MOMENT.
IN THE SECOND HEAT,
A SLIGHTLY MORE
PROFESSIONAL DISPLAY
IN THE SPIRIT OF
OUR SPLENDID PAST,
WHEN GLADIATOR
CLAUDIUS MARCUS
KILLED THE LAST
OF THE BARBARIANS,
WILLIAM B. HARRISON,
IN AN EXCELLENT EXAMPLE
OF--
[STATIC]
TRANSMISSION LOST,
SIR.
SHALL I TRY
TO GET IT BACK?
SLAVES AND GLADIATORS.
WHAT ARE WE SEEING,
A 20th-CENTURY ROME?
CAPTAIN, THE ONE
DESCRIBED AS THE BARBARIAN
IS ALSO LISTED HERE.
FLIGHT OFFICER
WILLIAM B. HARRISON
OF THE S.S. BEAGLE.
AT LEAST THERE WERE
SOME SURVIVORS DOWN THERE.
READY THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM, MR. SPOCK.
WE'RE BEAMING DOWN.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
YOU COULD HAVE SELECTED
A MORE CONVENIENT PLACE,
MR. SPOCK.
BUT HARDLY MORE
PRACTICAL, CAPTAIN.
CLOSE TO THE CITY
WE LOCATED,
BUT NOT POPULATED.
WE SHOULD NOT
BE OBSERVED.
FASCINATING.
THIS ATMOSPHERE
IS REMARKABLY SIMILAR
TO YOUR 20th CENTURY.
MODERATELY INDUSTRIALIZED
POLLUTION
CONTAINING SUBSTANTIAL AMOUNTS
OF CARBON MONOXIDE
AND PARTIALLY CONSUMED
HYDROCARBONS.
THE WORD WAS SMOG.
YES, I BELIEVE
THAT WAS THE TERM.
I HAD NO IDEA
YOU WERE THAT MUCH
OF A HISTORIAN, DOCTOR.
I AM NOT, MR. SPOCK.
I WAS SIMPLY
TRYING TO STOP YOU
FROM GIVING US
A WHOLE LECTURE
ON THE SUBJECT.
JIM, IS THERE
ANYTHING AT ALL
WE KNOW ABOUT
THIS PLANET?
THE S.S. BEAGLE
WAS THE FIRST SHIP
TO MAKE A SURVEY
OF THE STAR SECTOR
WHEN IT DISAPPEARED.
THEN THE PRIME DIRECTIVE
IS IN FULL FORCE, CAPTAIN?
NO IDENTIFICATION
OF SELF OR MISSION.
NO INTERFERENCE WITH
THE SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT
OF SAID PLANET.
NO REFERENCES TO SPACE
OR THE FACT THAT
THERE ARE OTHER WORLDS,
OR MORE
ADVANCED CIVILIZATIONS.
LET'S GO.
ONCE, JUST ONCE,
I'D LIKE TO BE ABLE
TO LAND SOMEPLACE
AND SAY,
"BEHOLD, I AM THE
ARCHANGEL GABRIEL."
I FAIL TO SEE
THE HUMOR IN THAT
SITUATION, DOCTOR.
NATURALLY.
YOU COULD HARDLY
CLAIM TO BE AN ANGEL
WITH THOSE
POINTED EARS,
MR. SPOCK,
BUT SAY YOU
LANDED SOMEPLACE
WITH A PITCHFORK.
[RIFLE SHOT]
DON'T MOVE!
HANDS IN THE AIR!
COMPLETE EARTH PARALLEL.
THE LANGUAGE HERE
IS ENGLISH.
I SAYS, DON'T MOVE!
I THINK HE MEANS IT,
SPOCK.
THERE WOULD SEEM TO BE
EVIDENCE TO THAT EFFECT.
WHO ARE YOU?
WE COME FROM ANOTHER...
PROVINCE.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
WHAT DO YOU
CALL THOSE?
I CALL THEM EARS.
ARE YOU TRYING
TO BE FUNNY?
NEVER.
COLLOQUIAL
20th-CENTURY ENGLISH--
AN AMAZING PARALLEL.
WE COME FROM A PLACE
THAT'S QUITE SOME
JOURNEY FROM HERE.
DOUBT IF YOU'VE
EVEN HEARD--
BEAUTIFUL.
PROBABLY SOME
NEWPRAETORIAN
PRETORIAN GUARD.
I SHOULD
KILL YOU HERE...
BUT SEPTIMUS
WOULD PROBABLY
BE DISPLEASED.
MOVE. MOVE.
[WHISTLES]
I DIDN'T HARM THEM,
SEPTIMUS,
AS MUCH AS
I WANTED TO.
KEEP ALWAYS IN
YOUR MIND, FLAVIUS,
THAT OUR WAY
IS PEACE.
FOR WHICH WE
ARE GRATEFUL,
FOR WE ARE
MEN OF PEACE
OURSELVES.
OH? ARE YOU CHILDREN
OF THE SUN?
WELL, UH, IF
YOU'RE SPEAKING
OF WORSHIPS
OF SORTS,
WE REPRESENT
MANY BELIEFS.
THERE IS ONLY ONE
TRUE BELIEF!
ROMAN BUTCHERS,
SENT HERE BY
THE FIRST CITIZEN.
DO WE LOOK LIKE
ANY ROMANS YOU EVER SAW?
THEN ARE YOU SLAVES
LIKE OURSELVES?
OUR PEOPLE DON'T BELIEVE
IN SLAVERY.
A ROMAN LIE.
WE MUST KILL THEM.
SIR, WE CAME HERE
LOOKING FOR SOME FRIENDS--
47 OF THEM WHO WERE
STRANDED HERE SOME
6 YEARS AGO.
THEY WORE CLOTHING
SIMILAR TO OURS.
HAVE YOU HEARD
OF SUCH MEN?
SEPTIMUS, I KNOW
KILLING IS EVIL,
BUT SOMETIMES
IT'S NECESSARY.
NO.
BUT THEY'VE LOCATED US,
OUR HIDING PLACE.
IT'S BETTER
TO KILL A FEW OF THEM
THAN ALL OF US.
WAIT.
I CAN PROVE
WE'RE TELLING THE TRUTH.
A SMALL DEVICE.
I'LL TAKE IT OUT
SLOWLY.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, LOCK IN ON
MY TRANSMISSION BEAM.
SCAN US.
SCANNING, SIR.
INCLUDING OURSELVES,
HOW MANY OF US ARE THERE?
12, CAPTAIN.
GOOD, SCOTTY.
CONTINUE SCANNING.
WE'LL MAINTAIN TRANSMISSION.
KIRK OUT.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS OUR SHIP,
SOMEWHERE AT SEA.
THAT'S ALL I CAN TELL YOU.
IF IT ISN'T SUFFICIENT,
YOU WILL HAVE TO KILL US.
TELL ME THE EMPIRE
HAS A DEVICE
LIKE THAT, FLAVIUS,
AND YOU MAY KILL THEM.
OTHERWISE, ACCEPT THEM
AS FRIENDS.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4040.7.
ON THE SURFACE OF PLANET 4,
SYSTEM 892,
THE LANDING PARTY
HAS WON THE CONFIDENCE
OF WHAT OBVIOUSLY IS
A GROUP OF RUNAWAY SLAVES.
THEY DWELL IN CAVES
NOT FAR FROM A LARGE CITY,
WEAR RAGS, LIVE UNDER
PRIMITIVE CONDITIONS.
BUT THEY ARE CREATURES
OF A HEAVILY INDUSTRIALIZED
20th-CENTURY-TYPE PLANET
VERY MUCH LIKE EARTH.
AN AMAZING EXAMPLE
OF HODGKIN'S LAW
OF PARALLEL PLANET
DEVELOPMENT,
BUT ON THIS "EARTH,"
ROME NEVER FELL.
A WORLD RULED BY EMPERORS
WHO CAN TRACE THEIR LINE
BACK 2,000 YEARS
TO THEIR OWN JULIUS
AND AUGUSTUS CAESARS.
NO, CAPTAIN.
I'M SURE I WOULD
HAVE HEARD
OF THE ARRIVAL
OF OTHER MEN
LIKE YOU.
PERHAPS YOU'VE HEARD,
LET'S SAY,
AN IMPOSSIBLE STORY
OR A RUMOR...
OF MEN WHO CAME
FROM THE SKY OR...
FROM OTHER WORLDS.
THERE ARE
NO OTHER WORLDS.
THE STARS.
LIGHTS SHINING THROUGH
FROM HEAVEN.
IT'S WHERE THE SUN IS.
BLESSED BE THE SUN.
YES, OF COURSE.
CAPTAIN, I THOUGHT
YOU MIGHT FIND THIS
INTERESTING.
SPOCK?
FASCINATING.
THE JUPITER 8.
CONVENTIONAL INTERNAL
COMBUSTION ENGINE.
YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT THE SMOG.
BUT THE JUPITER 8?
MARS TOOTHPASTE.
NEPTUNE BATH SALTS.
TAKEN FROM THE NAMES
OF FALSE GODS.
WHEN I WAS
A SENATOR,
I WORSHIPED THEM,
TOO,
BUT I HEARD THE
WORDS OF THE SUN.
I BECAME A BROTHER.
FOR THAT, THEY
MADE ME A SLAVE.
SEPTIMUS,
WE NEED YOUR HELP.
WE MUST GO
INTO THE CITY.
WE KNOW THAT ONE
OF OUR MISSING FRIENDS
WAS SEEN THERE RECENTLY.
MY ADVICE TO YOU
IS TO LEAVE.
GO BACK WHERE
YOU CAME FROM.
WE CAN'T DO THAT.
PERHAPS YOU KNOW HIS NAME--
MERIK. CAPTAIN MERIK.
MERIKUS?
YES. HE'S THE LEADER
OF OUR FRIENDS.
MERIKUS IS
FIRST CITIZEN.
BUTCHER.
THAT DOESN'T
SOUND LIKE
THE SAME MAN.
CAPTAIN, A LOGICAL
QUESTION, IF I MAY.
SEPTIMUS,
HOW MANY YEARS AGO
DID MERIKUS BECOME
YOUR FIRST CITIZEN?
PERHAPS FIVE YEARS.
ALMOST SIX.
I WAS THERE WHEN
HE BECAME LORD
OF THE GAMES.
IF HE IS
YOUR FRIEND,
YOU ARE NO
FRIENDS OF OURS.
SEPTIMUS, WHEREVER
WE MAY BE FROM,
YOU MUST BELIEVE THAT
IT IS ONE OF OUR MOST
IMPORTANT LAWS
THAT NONE OF US
INTERFERE WITH
THE AFFAIRS OF OTHERS.
IF CAPTAIN MERIK IS MERIKUS,
THEN HE HAS VIOLATED
THAT LAW,
AND HE MUST BE
TAKEN AWAY AND PUNISHED.
WILL YOU HELP US
TO GET TO THE TRUTH
OF ALL THIS?
FIRST I MUST DISCUSS IT
WITH THE OTHERS.
CURIOUS, CAPTAIN,
THE SIMILARITY IN NAMES.
WERE YOU TOLD
WHY MERIK WAS DROPPED
FROM THE SPACE ACADEMY?
HE FAILED
A PSYCHO-SIMULATOR TEST.
ALL IT TAKES IS
A SPLIT SECOND
OF INDECISION.
HARDLY THE TYPE TO BE
A POLITICAL STRONGMAN.
ODD THAT THESE PEOPLE
SHOULD WORSHIP THE SUN.
WHY, DOCTOR?
BECAUSE,
MY DEAR MR. SPOCK,
IT IS ILLOGICAL.
ROME HAD NO
SUN WORSHIPERS.
WHY SHOULD THEY
PARALLEL ROME
IN EVERY WAY EXCEPT ONE?
WE HAVE DECIDED.
FLAVIUS
WILL GUIDE YOU.
WE WILL
PROVIDE YOU
WITH SUITABLE
CLOTHING.
I CAUTION YOU,
TAKE GREAT CARE.
THE POLICE
ARE EVERYWHERE.
MAY THE BLESSINGS
OF THE SUN
BE UPON YOU.
WE'LL WAIT HERE
UNTIL DARK.
WERE YOU A SLAVE,
FLAVIUS?
YOU ARE BARBARIANS,
INDEED,
NOT TO KNOW
OF FLAVIUS MAXIMUS.
FOR SEVEN YEARS,
I WAS THE MOST
SUCCESSFUL GLADIATOR
IN THIS PROVINCE.
THEN YOU HEARD
THE WORD OF THE SUN?
YES.
THE WORDS OF PEACE
AND FREEDOM.
IT WASN'T EASY
FOR ME TO BELIEVE.
I WAS TRAINED
TO FIGHT.
BUT THE WORDS...
THE WORDS ARE TRUE.
THERE ARE MANY THINGS
I'D LIKE TO KNOW--
HOLD!
DON'T MOVE!
HANDS IN THE AIR!
FOUR FLEEING FISH.
A FINE HAUL.
FLAVIUS MAXIMUS.
YOU HAVE BEEN TOO LONG
ABSENT FROM THE GAMES,
FLAVIUS.
THE FIRST CITIZEN
WILL BE PLEASED.
RUNAWAY SLAVES
ARE ALWAYS WELCOME.
NO, NOT SLAVES.
BARBARIANS.
IT'S BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE I'VE WATCHED
BARBARIANS DIE
IN THE ARENA.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4040.9.
UNIFORMED POLICE
LIKE THOSE OF EARTH;
A GREAT CITY, LIKE ROME,
WITH AUTOMOBILES;
ASTONISHING SIMILARITIES
TO 20th-CENTURY EARTH,
DOWN TO THE FINE CARBON STEEL
IN THE BARS.
TELL MERIKUS
I'D LIKE TO SEE HIM.
THE FIRST CITIZEN?
WHY WOULD HE BOTHER
WITH ARENA BAIT
LIKE YOU?
TELL HIM IT'S JIM KIRK,
PERHAPS A FRIEND.
PERHAPS?
WELL, IF I AM A FRIEND
AND YOU DON'T TELL HIM,
DO YOU REALLY
WANT TO RISK THAT?
BUT IF THERE
HAVE BEEN SLAVES
FOR OVER 2,000 YEARS,
HASN'T THERE ALWAYS BEEN
DISCONTENT, RUNAWAYS?
LONG AGO, THERE
WERE REBELLIONS,
BUT THEY WERE SUPPRESSED.
AND WITH EACH CENTURY,
THE SLAVES ACQUIRED
MORE RIGHTS UNDER THE LAW.
THEY RECEIVED RIGHTS
TO MEDICINE,
THE RIGHT TO GOVERNMENT
PAYMENTS IN THEIR OLD AGE,
AND THEY SLOWLY LEARNED
TO BE CONTENT.
EVEN MORE FASCINATING.
SLAVERY EVOLVING
INTO AN INSTITUTION
WITH GUARANTEED
MEDICAL PAYMENTS,
OLD-AGE PENSIONS.
QUITE LOGICAL,
I'D SAY, MR. SPOCK,
JUST AS IT'S LOGICAL
THAT
A 20th-CENTURY ROME
WOULD USE TELEVISION
TO SHOW ITS
GLADIATOR CONTESTS
OR NAME A NEW CAR
THE JUPITER 8.
DOCTOR, IF I WERE ABLE
TO SHOW EMOTION,
YOUR NEW INFATUATION
WITH THAT TERM
WOULD BEGIN TO ANNOY ME.
WHAT TERM?
LOGIC?
MEDICAL MEN ARE TRAINED
IN LOGIC, MR. SPOCK.
REALLY, DOCTOR,
I HAD NO IDEA
THEY WERE TRAINED.
WATCHING YOU,
I ASSUMED IT WAS
TRIAL AND ERROR.
ARE THEY ENEMIES,
CAPTAIN?
I'M NOT SURE
THEY'RE SURE.
WHEN THE SLAVES BEGAN
TO WORSHIP THE SUN,
THEY BECAME DISCONTENT AGAIN.
WHEN DID
ALL THIS HAPPEN?
LONG AGO.
PERHAPS AS LONG AGO
AS THE BEGINNING
OF THE EMPIRE.
THE MESSAGE
OF THE SUN,
THAT ALL MEN
ARE BROTHERS,
WAS KEPT FROM US.
PERHAPS I'M A FOOL
TO BELIEVE IT.
IT DOES OFTEN SEEM
THAT MAN MUST FIGHT
TO LIVE.
YOU GO ON BELIEVING IT,
FLAVIUS.
ALL MEN ARE BROTHERS.
YOUR FRIENDS ARE
WAITING FOR YOU.
YOU'VE ALREADY
BEEN MATCHED
FOR THE MORNING
GAMES. COME.
I WILL NOT FIGHT.
I'M A BROTHER
OF THE SUN.
PUT A SWORD
IN YOUR HAND,
AND YOU'LL FIGHT.
I KNOW YOU, FLAVIUS.
YOU'RE AS PEACEFUL
AS A BULL.
YOU THREE
COME WITH US.
THREE AGAINST THREE.
WE MAY NEVER HAVE
A BETTER CHANCE.
NO TALKING. OUTSIDE.
I DOUBT IF HE'LL
GET VERY FAR.
HE FEELS ILL.
I DO?
OUTSIDE!
ALL RIGHT, BUT
HE'LL DOUBLE OVER
BEFORE WE GET
VERY FAR.
NO, I--I THINK
I CAN WALK.
I'LL--I'LL TRY.
OOH!
[KIRK]
LET'S GO.
WELL DONE, JIM...
BUT I'M AFRAID
IT ISN'T THAT EASY.
THEY'VE BEEN HANDLING SLAVES
HERE FOR 2,000 YEARS.
BUT IT WAS EXCITING.
THEY'D DO WELL
IN THE ARENA.
CAPTAIN MERIK, IS IT?
YES, IT'S ME.
THIS IS OUR PROCONSUL
CLAUDIUS MARCUS.
BUT THIS IS NO PLACE
FOR A REUNION.
THIS WAY.
YOUR FRIENDS, TOO.
THERE'S LOTS
TO TALK ABOUT,
LOTS TO EXPLAIN.
I AGREE.
DON'T JUDGE ME BEFORE
YOU KNOW THE FACTS.
COME ON. WE CAN
TALK FREELY HERE.
THE PROCONSUL KNOWS
WHO AND WHAT WE ARE.
YOU CAN
LEAVE US.
WELL,
A CELEBRATION.
A MEETING
OF OLD FRIENDS.
PREPARE FOOD
FOR OUR FRIENDS.
THEY'VE COME FROM
A GREAT DISTANCE.
GREAT DISTANCE,
INDEED.
SO THIS IS A VULCAN.
INTERESTING.
FROM WHAT
I'VE HEARD,
I WISH I HAD 50 OF
YOU FOR THE ARENA.
THIS OTHER IS
YOUR SHIP'S
SURGEON?
McCOY.
IT'S A PITY WE CAN'T
LET HIM LOOSE
IN OUR HOSPITALS.
OUR LEVEL
OF MEDICINE
WOULD IMPROVE
IMMEASURABLY,
I'M SURE.
COME. YOU MUST
BE HUNGRY.
GENTLEMEN.
OH, TRY THE SPARROW
BROILED IN GARUM.
DELICIOUS.
OR PERHAPS SOME
OF THIS ROAST KID.
LOVELY THING,
ISN'T SHE?
[CHUCKLES]
MERIK,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE HAD METEOR
DAMAGE, JIM.
I WENT ASHORE
WITH A LANDING PARTY
TO LOOK FOR IRIDIUM ORE
FOR REPAIRS,
AND I MET THIS GENTLEMAN.
GO ON.
HE CONVINCED ME
IT WOULD BE UNFAIR
TO THIS WORLD
TO CARRY WORD OF
THEIR EXISTENCE ELSEWHERE.
CONTAMINATION.
CAN'T RISK THAT.
OH, UH, YOU'LL
UNDERSTAND AS YOU
LEARN MORE ABOUT US.
SO I MADE THE DECISION
TO STAY.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR CREW?
DID THEY VOLUNTARILY BEAM--
COME ASHORE?
THIS IS
AN ORDERED WORLD, JIM,
A CONSERVATIVE WORLD
BASED ON TIME-HONORED
ROMAN STRENGTHS AND VIRTUES.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR CREW?
THERE'S BEEN NO WAR HERE
FOR OVER 400 YEARS, JIM.
COULD, LET'S SAY,
YOUR LAND
OF THAT SAME ERA
MAKE THAT SAME BOAST?
I THINK YOU CAN SEE
WHY THEY DON'T WANT
TO HAVE THEIR STABILITY
CONTAMINATED
BY DANGEROUS IDEAS
OF OTHER WAYS AND PLACES.
INTERESTING, AND GIVEN
A CONSERVATIVE EMPIRE,
QUITE UNDERSTANDABLE.
ARE YOU
OUT OF YOUR HEAD?
I SAID I UNDERSTOOD IT,
DOCTOR.
I FIND THE CHECKS
AND BALANCES OF
THIS CIVILIZATION
QUITE ILLUMINATING.
NEXT HE'LL BE TELLING US
HE PREFERS IT
OVER EARTH HISTORY.
THEY DO SEEM TO HAVE
ESCAPED THE CARNAGE
OF YOUR FIRST THREE
WORLD WARS, DOCTOR.
THEY HAVE SLAVERY,
GLADIATORIAL GAMES,
DESPOTISM--
SITUATIONS QUITE FAMILIAR
TO THE 6 MILLION
WHO DIED IN YOUR FIRST
WORLD WAR,
THE 11 MILLION WHO DIED
IN YOUR SECOND,
THE 37 MILLION
WHO DIED IN YOUR THIRD...
SHALL I GO ON?
INTERESTING.
AND YOU, CAPTAIN...
WHICH WORLD
DO YOU PREFER?
MY WORLD, PROCONSUL,
IS MY VESSEL,
MY OATH, MY CREW.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR VESSEL
YOU'VE EXPLAINED.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR OATH
IS OBVIOUS.
AND AS FOR MY MEN,
THOSE THAT WERE ABLE
TO ADAPT TO THIS WORLD
ARE STILL ALIVE.
THOSE WHO COULDN'T
ADAPT ARE DEAD.
THAT'S THE WAY
AS WITH LIFE EVERYWHERE,
ISN'T IT?
YOU SENT
YOUR OWN MEN
INTO THE ARENA?
JUST AS I DID, JIM,
YOU'RE GOING TO ORDER
YOUR OWN PEOPLE ASHORE.
YOU KNOW
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
STARFLEET REGULATIONS--
ARE DESIGNED
TO CIRCUMVENT
ANY SUCH ORDER.
THERE MAY BE OVER 400 MEN
ON YOUR SHIP, CAPTAIN,
BUT THEY CAN BE
BROUGHT DOWN
IF IT'S HANDLED PROPERLY,
SAY, A FEW AT A TIME.
YOU SEE,
I HAVE THE ADVANTAGE
OF A TRAINED SHIP CAPTAIN
TO TELL ME WHAT IS
AND WHAT IS NOT POSSIBLE.
YOUR COMMUNICATOR,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
NOW, DO SAVE US ALL
A LOT OF UNNECESSARY
TROUBLE
AND ISSUE
THE APPROPRIATE ORDERS.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE
ARRIVING SOON, ANYWAY, JIM--
A RECON PARTY,
THEN A RESCUE PARTY,
THEN ANOTHER
RESCUE PARTY.
I HAD LESS MEN.
IT ADDED UP THE SAME.
DO YOU
REALLY BELIEVE
I COULD BE MADE
TO ORDER MY OWN
PEOPLE DOWN?
I BELIEVE THIS, CAPTAIN.
THAT YOU WOULD DO
ALMOST ANYTHING...
RATHER THAN SEE
THESE TWO DEAR FRIENDS
PUT SLOWLY TO DEATH.
JIM.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
BRIDGE. SCOTT HERE.
SCOTTY, IF YOU
HAVE A FIX--
STAND BY, SCOTTY.
VERY WISE OF YOU, CAPTAIN.
NO POINT IN SENDING UP
BULLET-RIDDEN CORPSES.
YET ON THE OTHER HAND,
MY CHIEF ENGINEER'S
STANDING BY FOR A MESSAGE.
I DO HOPE SO,
FOR YOUR SAKE.
NOW, CAPTAIN,
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO
ORDER YOUR MEN TO DO?
IF I BROUGHT DOWN
A HUNDRED OF THEM
ARMED WITH PHASERS...
YOU COULD PROBABLY DEFEAT
THE COMBINED ARMIES
OF OUR ENTIRE EMPIRE...
AND VIOLATE YOUR OATH
REGARDING NONINTERFERENCE
WITH OTHER SOCIETIES.
I BELIEVE YOU ALL SWEAR
YOU'LL DIE
BEFORE YOU'D VIOLATE
THAT DIRECTIVE.
AM I RIGHT?
[MR. SPOCK]
QUITE CORRECT.
MUST YOU ALWAYS BE
SO BLASTED HONEST?
BUT ON THE OTHER HAND,
WHY EVEN BOTHER
TO SEND YOUR MEN DOWN?
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
YOUR VESSEL COULD LAY WASTE
TO THE ENTIRE SURFACE
OF THE WORLD...
OH, BUT THERE'S THAT
PRIME DIRECTIVE
IN THE WAY AGAIN.
CAN'T INTERFERE.
JIM, YOU'VE ALREADY
STARTED A MESSAGE.
YOUR ENGINEER'S WAITING.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
SCOTTY. SORRY
TO KEEP YOU WAITING.
WE WERE BECOMING
CONCERNED, CAPTAIN.
YOU WERE
A BIT OVERDUE.
ORDER YOUR OFFICERS
TO COME DOWN.
CONDITION GREEN,
ALL'S WELL. KIRK OUT.
GUARDS, TAKE THEM.
PREPARE THEM
FOR THE GAMES.
AH...THAT WAS
STUPID, JIM.
THIS IS NOT
AN ACADEMY
TRAINING TEST.
THIS IS FOR REAL.
THEY'RE TAKING YOU
TO DIE.
SHIP'S LOG--
STARDATE 4041.2.
CHIEF ENGINEER SCOTT
RECORDING.
CAPTAIN KIRK
AND HIS LANDING PARTY
HAVE CHECKED IN,
BUT THEY HAVE USED THE CODE
TERM CONDITION GREEN,
WHICH MEANS
THEY'RE IN TROUBLE,
BUT IT ALSO PROHIBITS
MY TAKING ANY ACTION.
MR. CHEKOV, PINPOINT
POWER SOURCE LOCATIONS--
TYPE POWER, LOAD FACTORS,
AND HOW MUCH OUR BEAMS
WILL HAVE TO PULL
TO OVERLOAD THEM.
THAT MAY
TAKE SOME TIME.
LET IT TAKE TIME, LAD.
THEY'RE IN TROUBLE,
AND I'M UNDER ORDERS
NOT TO INTERFERE.
HOWEVER,
NO ORDER CAN STOP ME
FROM FRIGHTENING THEM.
MAY DO NO GOOD,
BUT IT MAY SUGGEST
TO SOMEONE
JUST WHAT A STARSHIP
CAN REALLY DO.
AYE.
GOOD EVENING,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
LIVE AND DIRECT
FROM CITY ARENA
AND IN COLOR,
WE BRING YOU
NAME THE WINNER,
BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
BY YOUR JUPITER 8 DEALERS
FROM COAST TO COAST.
IN JUST A MOMENT,
TONIGHT'S FIRST HEAT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE COMMERCIAL,
PROCONSUL, FOR 40 SECONDS,
THEN WE'LL BE BACK LIVE.
STAND BY. 10 SECONDS.
AND FIRST TONIGHT,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
A SURPRISE EXTRA.
IN THE FAR CORNER,
A PAIR OF HIGHLY
AGGRESSIVE BARBARIANS--
STRONG, INTELLIGENT,
WITH STRANGE WAYS,
AND I'M SURE FULL
OF A LOT OF SURPRISES.
AND FACING THEM,
TWO FAVORITES HERE
FROM PREVIOUS ENCOUNTERS,
ACHILLES AND FLAVIUS.
[APPLAUSE]
VICTORY OR DEATH?
AND FOR WHICH OF THEM?
WELL, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
YOU KNOW JUST AS MUCH ABOUT THAT
AT THIS MOMENT AS I DO
BECAUSE THIS IS
YOUR PROGRAM.
YOU NAME THE WINNER.
[CANNED CHEERING]
[CANNED BOOING]
I DON'T MIND FIGHTING,
BUT WHY YOU?
BEGIN!
FLAVIUS MAY BE GETTING OFF
TO A SLOW START,
BUT HE'S NEVER DISAPPOINTED
THIS CROWD--
AND THERE'S A CLOSE ONE.
THE BARBARIAN WITH
THE POINTY EARS
SEEMS TO BE IN TROUBLE.
I TELL YOU,
I'M WELL ABLE
TO DEFEAT YOU.
FIGHT, BARBARIAN.
MOST OF MY MEN
WENT THE SAME WAY.
I HOPED I WOULD
FEEL IT LESS
WITH YOURS.
I DO NOT
WANT TO INJURE YOU.
OH!
FIGHT, YOU TWO.
YOU BRING THIS
NETWORK'S RATINGS
DOWN, FLAVIUS,
AND WE'LL DO
A SPECIAL ON YOU.
QUESTION, CAPTAIN?
THE RULES.
IF SPOCK SHOULD FINISH
HIS MAN OFF FIRST,
WOULD HE BE ABLE TO HELP--
WE BELIEVE MEN SHOULD FIGHT
THEIR OWN BATTLES.
ONLY THE WEAK WILL DIE,
MY WORD AS A ROMAN.
READY TO ORDER
YOUR MEN DOWN, CAPTAIN?
MAYBE NOW
YOU UNDERSTAND
WHY I GAVE IN, JIM.
THE ROMANS
HAVE ALWAYS BEEN
THE STRONGEST,
AND THEY'VE
HAD PRACTICE
FOR OVER 2,000 YEARS
IN ENSLAVING MEN,
USING THEM,
KILLING THEM.
QUITE TRUE, CAPTAIN KIRK.
THE GAMES HAVE ALWAYS
STRENGTHENED US.
DEATH BECOMES
A FAMILIAR PATTERN.
WE DON'T FEAR IT
AS YOU DO.
AT LEAST
DEFEND YOURSELF.
I AM DEFENDING MYSELF!
NOT LIKE THAT,
YOU FOOL. HOLD
YOUR WEAPON HIGHER.
ADMIT IT.
YOU FIND THESE GAMES
FRIGHTENING, REVOLTING.
PROCONSUL,
IN SOME PARTS
OF THE GALAXY,
I HAVE SEEN FORMS
OF ENTERTAINMENT
THAT MAKES
THIS LOOK LIKE
A FOLK DANCE.
CERTAIN THIS ISN'T
DIFFERENT, CAPTAIN?
THOSE ARE YOUR MEN DYING,
NOT STRANGERS.
I'VE HAD TO SELECT
MEN TO DIE BEFORE
SO THAT OTHERS
COULD BE SAVED.
YOU'RE A CLEVER LIAR,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
MERIKUS WAS
A SPACESHIP CAPTAIN.
I'VE OBSERVED HIM
THOROUGHLY.
YOUR SPECIES HAS
NO SUCH STRENGTH.
HE COMMANDS NOT
JUST A SPACESHIP,
PROCONSUL,
BUT A STARSHIP.
A VERY SPECIAL
VESSEL AND CREW.
I TRIED
FOR SUCH A COMMAND.
I SEE NO EVIDENCE
OF SUPERIORITY.
THEY FIGHT NO BETTER
THAN YOUR MEN DID, MERIKUS.
PERHAPS NOT AS WELL.
[INDISTINCT].
NEED ANY HELP,
DOCTOR?
WHATEVER GAVE YOU THAT IDEA?
FIGHT, YOU
POINTED-EAR FREAK!
YOU TELL HIM, BUSTER.
OF ALL THE COMPLETELY...
RIDICULOUS...
ILLOGICAL QUESTIONS...
I EVER HEARD IN MY LIFE!
A CLEAR FOUL, PROCONSUL.
YOUR DECISION?
YOUR OPINION, MERIKUS?
AFTER ALL,
THEY'RE LIKE YOURSELF.
IT'S YOUR DECISION,
PROCONSUL.
YOUR OPINION, CAPTAIN KIRK?
YOU LIKE ME
TO KILL THEM NOW?
AN EASY DEATH?
THEN YOU'D GLADLY ACCEPT
WHATEVER HAPPENS TO YOU.
TAKE THEM BACK
TO THEIR CAGE.
WELL, IT WON'T GO THAT
EASILY FOR THEM, CAPTAIN...
NOR FOR YOU.
TAKE HIM
TO MY QUARTERS.
I WAS TOLD
TO WAIT FOR YOU...
AND PROVIDE
WINE, FOOD,
WHATEVER YOU WISH.
I AM PROCONSUL'S
SLAVE DRUSILLA...
ALTHOUGH
FOR THIS EVENING...
FOR THIS EVENING,
I WAS TOLD
I AM YOUR SLAVE.
COMMAND ME.
IT WON'T WORK.
WHAT WILL NOT WORK?
WHATEVER HE HAS IN MIND
OR WHATEVER TRICKS.
YOU HEAR THAT, PROCONSUL?
IT WON'T WORK.
I'M NOT COOPERATING.
I MAY DIE,
BUT YOU WON'T GET
ANY ENTERTAINMENT
OUT OF IT.
WE'RE ALONE.
PLEASE BELIEVE ME.
I'VE NEVER LIED
TO ONE WHO OWNS ME.
ANGRY, MR. SPOCK?
OR FRUSTRATED,
PERHAPS?
SUCH EMOTIONS
ARE FOREIGN TO ME,
DOCTOR.
I'M MERELY TESTING
THE STRENGTH OF THE DOOR.
FOR THE 15th TIME.
SPOCK.
SPOCK, UH...
I KNOW WE'VE, UH...
HAD OUR
DISAGREEMENTS.
UH, MAYBE
THEY'RE JOKES.
I DON'T KNOW.
AS JIM SAYS,
WE'RE NOT OFTEN
SURE OURSELVES
SOMETIMES,
BUT WHAT I'M TRYING
TO SAY IS--
DOCTOR, I AM SEEKING
A MEANS OF ESCAPE.
WILL YOU PLEASE BE BRIEF?
WELL, WHAT
I'M TRYING TO SAY
IS YOU SAVED MY LIFE
IN THE ARENA.
YES, THAT'S QUITE TRUE.
I'M TRYING
TO THANK YOU,
YOU POINTED-EARED
HOBGOBLIN!
OH, YES.
YOU HUMANS HAVE
THAT EMOTIONAL NEED
TO EXPRESS GRATITUDE.
YOU'RE WELCOME, I BELIEVE,
IS THE CORRECT RESPONSE.
HOWEVER, DOCTOR,
YOU MUST REMEMBER
THAT I AM ENTIRELY
MOTIVATED BY LOGIC.
THE LOSS OF OUR
SHIP'S SURGEON,
WHATEVER I THINK OF
HIS RELATIVE SKILL,
WOULD MEAN A REDUCTION
IN THE EFFICIENCY
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
AND THEREFORE--
DO YOU KNOW WHY
YOU'RE NOT AFRAID
TO DIE, SPOCK?
YOU'RE MORE AFRAID
OF LIVING.
EACH DAY YOU STAY ALIVE
IS JUST ONE MORE DAY
YOU MIGHT SLIP
AND LET YOUR
HUMAN HALF PEEK OUT.
THAT'S IT, ISN'T IT?
INSECURITY.
WHY, YOU WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO
WITH A GENUINE, WARM,
DECENT FEELING.
REALLY, DOCTOR?
I KNOW.
I'M WORRIED
ABOUT JIM, TOO.
VERY GOOD.
EXCELLENT.
I WAS CONCERNED.
I AM ORDERED
TO PLEASE YOU.
I'VE BEEN IN
SOME STRANGE WORLDS,
STRANGE CUSTOMS.
PERHAPS THIS IS CONSIDERED
TORTURE HERE.
TORTURE?
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
I DO NOT WISH
TO SEE YOU TORTURED
IN ANY WAY.
AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF PAIN,
YOU WILL TELL ME?
YOU'LL BE THE FIRST
TO KNOW.
CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY.
I WAS DETAINED.
SHOULD WE HAVE
OUR LITTLE TALK NOW?
SO FAR ON THIS PLANET
WE'VE KEPT YOU
RATHER BUSY.
I DON'T WONDER
YOU SLEPT THROUGH
THE AFTERNOON.
BY THE WAY,
ONE OF THE COMMUNICATORS
WE TOOK FROM YOU IS MISSING.
WAS IT MY PRETTY DRUSILLA
BY ANY CHANCE?
SEE IF HE HAS IT...
NOT THAT I WOULD
HAVE PUNISHED HER.
I WOULD HAVE
BLAMED YOU.
YOU'RE A ROMAN,
KIRK,
OR YOU SHOULD
HAVE BEEN.
IT'S NOT
ON HIS PERSON?
NO, PROCONSUL.
I AM SORRY
I WAS DETAINED.
I TRUST THERE WAS
NOTHING FURTHER
YOU REQUIRED?
NOTHING
EXCEPT PERHAPS
AN EXPLANATION.
BECAUSE YOU'RE A MAN,
I OWE YOU THAT.
YOU MUST DIE SHORTLY,
AND BECAUSE YOU ARE A MAN...
WOULD YOU LEAVE US,
MERIK?
THE THOUGHTS
OF ONE MAN TO ANOTHER
CANNOT POSSIBLY
INTEREST YOU.
BECAUSE YOU ARE A MAN,
I GAVE YOU
SOME LAST HOURS
AS A MAN.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE MUST DEMONSTRATE
THAT DEFIANCE
IS INTOLERABLE.
OF COURSE.
BUT I'VE LEARNED
TO RESPECT YOU.
I PROMISE YOU
YOU WILL DIE EASILY, QUICKLY.
I THANK YOU.
AND MY FRIENDS?
WHEN THEIR TIME COMES,
THE SAME, OF COURSE.
GUARDS.
TAKE HIM
TO THE ARENA.
OH, WE'VE PREEMPTED
15 MINUTES
ON THE EARLY SHOW
FOR YOU...
IN FULL COLOR.
WE GUARANTEE YOU
A SPLENDID AUDIENCE.
OH, YOU MAY NOT
UNDERSTAND
BECAUSE YOU'RE CENTURIES
BEYOND ANYTHING
AS CRUDE AS TELEVISION.
I'VE HEARD IT WAS...
SIMILAR.
ENTERPRISE LOG--
ENGINEER SCOTT REPORTING.
ALL BANKS IN READINESS
FOR DISRUPTION
OF POWER SOURCES
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE.
GOOD EVENING,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
BEFORE TONIGHT'S FIRST HEAT,
A SIMPLE EXECUTION.
STAY TUNED TO THIS CHANNEL.
THERE'S A LOT OF EXCITEMENT
COMING YOUR WAY.
MAKE IT A QUICK,
SINGLE THRUST.
DON'T MOVE.
YOU'LL ONLY DIE HARDER.
MURDERERS!
IF YOU WANT DEATH,
FIGHT ME!
OOH!
NOW, MR. CHEKOV!
ACTIVATE!
GUARDS,
DON'T LET HIM ESCAPE!
GUARDS!
JIM!
STAND BACK.
OBSOLETE,
BUT EFFECTIVE.
WHAT HAPPENED, JIM?
WHAT DID THEY
DO TO YOU, CAPTAIN?
THEY THREW ME
A FEW CURVES.
NO TIME TO EXPLAIN.
HOLD!
WE'RE IN EACH OTHER'S
LINE OF FIRE.
I PITY YOU,
CAPTAIN MERIK,
BUT AT LEAST WATCH
AND SEE HOW MEN DIE.
SWORDS ONLY!
STARSHIP,
LOCK IN ON THIS.
THREE TO BEAM--
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
READY TO BEAM UP
THREE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 4041.7.
NOTE COMMENDATION TO
ENGINEERING OFFICER SCOTT.
DESPITE
ENORMOUS TEMPTATION
AND STRONG
PERSONAL FEELINGS,
HE OBEYED
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE.
HIS TEMPORARY BLACKOUT
OF THE CITY BELOW
RESULTED IN NO INTERFERENCE
WITH THE SOCIETY
AND YET SAVED
THE LIVES OF MYSELF
AND THE LANDING PARTY.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
GENTLEMEN.
CAPTAIN, I SEE
ON YOUR REPORT
FLAVIUS WAS KILLED.
I AM SORRY.
I LIKED THAT HUGE
SUN WORSHIPER.
I WISH WE
COULD HAVE EXAMINED
THAT BELIEF OF HIS
MORE CLOSELY.
IT SEEMS ILLOGICAL
FOR A SUN WORSHIPER
TO DEVELOP A PHILOSOPHY
OF TOTAL BROTHERHOOD.
SUN WORSHIP IS
USUALLY A PRIMITIVE
SUPERSTITION RELIGION.
I'M AFRAID YOU HAVE IT
ALL WRONG, MR. SPOCK,
ALL OF YOU.
I'VE BEEN MONITORING
SOME OF THEIR OLD-STYLE
RADIO WAVES,
THE EMPIRE SPOKESMAN TRYING
TO RIDICULE THEIR RELIGION,
BUT HE COULDN'T.
WELL, DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
IT'S NOT THE SUN
UP IN THE SKY.
IT'S THE SON OF GOD.
CAESAR...
AND CHRIST,
THEY HAD THEM BOTH.
AND THE WORD IS SPREADING
ONLY NOW.
A PHILOSOPHY
OF TOTAL LOVE
AND TOTAL
BROTHERHOOD.
IT WILL REPLACE
THEIR IMPERIAL ROME,
BUT IT WILL HAPPEN
IN THEIR 20th CENTURY.
WOULDN'T IT BE
SOMETHING TO WATCH,
TO BE A PART OF?
TO SEE IT HAPPEN
ALL OVER AGAIN?
MR. CHEKOV,
TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR ONE.
AYE, SIR.