CAPTAIN'S LOG.
USING THE LIGHT SPEED
BREAKAWAY FACTOR,
THE "ENTERPRISE" HAS MOVED
BACK THROUGH TIME
TO THE 20th CENTURY.
WE ARE NOW IN
EXTENDED ORBIT AROUND EARTH,
USING OUR SHIP'S
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
TO REMAIN UNOBSERVED.
OUR MISSION--
HISTORICAL RESEARCH.
WE ARE MONITORING
EARTH COMMUNICATIONS
TO FIND OUT HOW OUR PLANET
SURVIVED DESPERATE PROBLEMS
IN THE YEAR 1968.
ALERT STATUS.
FORCE SHIELDS ON MAXIMUM.
LESLIE, BEGIN SENSOR SCAN.
TRANSPORTER ROOM
TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
IT APPEARS WE HAVE
ACCIDENTALLY INTERCEPTED
SOMEONE'S TRANSPORTER
BEAM, CAPTAIN.
IT'S INCREDIBLY POWERFUL.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THE 20th CENTURY
HAD NO SUCH--
CAPTAIN, SOMETHING
IS BEAMING ABOARD
THIS VESSEL.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
THE BEAM IS ORIGINATING
AT LEAST 1,000
LIGHT YEARS AWAY.
NO TRANSPORTER BEAM
CAN REACH THAT FAR,
NOT EVEN
IN OUR CENTURY!
SOMETHING'S
SHAKING US APART.
IT'S LOCKED, SIR.
IT'S LEFT OUR
CIRCUITS WIDE OPEN.
[BEEP BEEP]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
SOMETHING IS
BEAMING ABOARD.
[MEOW]
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
WHY HAVE YOU
INTERCEPTED ME?
SECURITY.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
ON THE DOUBLE.
ON OUR WAY, SIR.
PLEASE IDENTIFY
YOURSELVES.
THIS IS THE UNITED
SPACESHIP "ENTERPRISE."
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK...
COMMANDING.
YES, I HEARD HIM,
ISIS.
I'M ABOARD
A SPACE VESSEL.
FROM WHAT PLANET?
EARTH.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IN THIS TIME PERIOD,
THERE WEREN'T--
HUMANS
WITH A VULCAN. YOU--
YOU'RE FROM
THE FUTURE, CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO
BEAM ME
DOWN TO EARTH
IMMEDIATELY.
PHASERS ON STUN.
[MEOW]
CAREFUL, ISIS.
ALL RIGHT.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
MY NAME IS GARY SEVEN.
I AM A HUMAN BEING
FROM THE 20th CENTURY.
I WAS ON MY WAY--
HUMANS
OF THE 20th CENTURY
DO NOT GO BEAMING
AROUND THE GALAXY,
MR. SEVEN.
I'VE BEEN LIVING
ON ANOTHER PLANET
FAR MORE ADVANCED.
I WAS BEAMING TO EARTH
WHEN YOU INTERCEPTED ME.
THE LOCATION
OF THAT PLANET?
THEY WISH THEIR EXISTENCE
KEPT SECRET.
EVEN IN YOUR TIME,
IT WILL REMAIN UNKNOWN.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO HIDE
A WHOLE PLANET.
IMPOSSIBLE FOR YOU.
NOT FOR THEM.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I AM OF THIS TIME PERIOD.
YOU ARE NOT.
YOU INTERFERE WITH ME
WITH WHAT I HAVE
TO DO DOWN THERE,
AND YOU'LL CHANGE HISTORY.
YOU'LL DESTROY
THE EARTH...
AND PROBABLY
YOURSELVES, TOO.
IF WHAT HE SAYS
IS TRUE, CAPTAIN,
EVERY SECOND WE DELAY
HIM COULD BE DANGEROUS.
AND IF HE'S LYING...
THIS IS THE MOST
CRITICAL PERIOD
IN EARTH'S HISTORY.
THE PLANET I'M FROM
WANTS TO HELP EARTH
SURVIVE.
WHAT IF IT TURNS OUT
YOU'RE
AN INVADING ALIEN
FROM THE FUTURE?
A MOST DIFFICULT
DECISION, CAPTAIN.
I CAN'T
BEAM YOU DOWN
WITHOUT FURTHER
PROOF ONE WAY
OR THE OTHER.
SECURITY.
CONFINEMENT.
THIS WAY, PLEASE.
SICK BAY.
McCOY HERE.
[MRROWRRR]
JIM...JIM!
JIM.
WHAT'S GOING ON THERE?
SICK BAY
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
JIM, WHAT'S GOING ON
DOWN THERE?
BONES, CHECK THE
PRISONER YOU'LL FIND
IN SECURITY
CONFINEMENT.
I WANT A MEDICAL
ANALYSIS FAST.
IS HE
OR ISN'T HE HUMAN?
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
SUPPLEMENTAL.
A MAN IN A 20th-CENTURY
BUSINESS SUIT--
WHAT IS HE?
NOT EVEN SPOCK'S VULCAN
NECK PINCH COULD STOP HIM.
WITHOUT OUR PHASERS,
HE WOULD HAVE OVERPOWERED
ALL FIVE OF US.
I FIND IT DIFFICULT
TO BELIEVE
THE MYSTERIOUS MR. SEVEN
CAN BE HUMAN,
AND YET, SUPPOSE HE IS?
WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF THE CAT, MR. SPOCK?
QUITE A LOVELY
ANIMAL, CAPTAIN.
I FIND MYSELF
STRANGELY
DRAWN TO IT.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
ALL SCIENCE,
ENGINEERING, AND
SUPERVISORY PERSONNEL,
LOCK INTO
THE BRIEFING ROOM.
OUR NEXT DECISION
CAN BE OF ENORMOUS
CONSEQUENCE,
NOT ONLY TO US
BUT TO EARTH'S
ENTIRE FUTURE.
YOU'VE ALREADY
BEEN GIVEN AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS WE HAVE.
PLEASE BREAK IN
AT ANY TIME
WITH ANALYSIS
OF THAT INFORMATION.
NAVIGATION REPORT.
WE'VE ANALYZED
THE DIRECTION
OF HIS BEAM, SIR.
OUR STAR MAPS SHOW
NO HABITABLE PLANETS
IN THAT AREA
OF THE GALAXY.
HE DID SAY HIS
PLANET WAS
HIDDEN, CAPTAIN.
ENGINEERING.
STILL UNABLE
TO ANALYZE IT, SIR.
IT WAS SO POWERFUL,
IT FUSED MOST OF
OUR RECORDING CIRCUITS.
COULD HAVE BROUGHT
HIM BACK THROUGH
GREAT DISTANCES
COULD HAVE BROUGHT HIM
BACK THROUGH TIME.
THERE'S NO WAY
FOR US TO KNOW.
MR. SPOCK,
HISTORICAL
REPORT.
CURRENT EARTH CRISES
WOULD FILL A TAPE
BANK, CAPTAIN.
THERE WILL BE
AN IMPORTANT
ASSASSINATION TODAY,
AN EQUALLY DANGEROUS
GOVERNMENT COUP IN ASIA,
AND THIS COULD BE
HIGHLY CRITICAL--
THE LAUNCHING OF
AN ORBITAL NUCLEAR
WARHEAD PLATFORM
BY THE UNITED STATES
COUNTERING A SIMILAR
LAUNCH BY OTHER POWERS.
WEREN'T ORBITAL
NUCLEAR DEVICES
ONE OF THIS ERA'S
GREATEST PROBLEMS?
MOST DEFINITELY.
ONCE THE SKY
WAS FULL OF
ORBITING H-BOMBS.
THE SLIGHTEST MISTAKE
COULD HAVE BROUGHT ONE
DOWN BY ACCIDENT,
SETTING OFF
A NUCLEAR HOLOCAUST.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
McCOY HERE.
Kirk:
BONES, HURRY UP
WITH THAT REPORT.
JOIN ME IN
THE BRIEFING ROOM
WITH YOUR ANALYSIS.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[ELECTRONIC TONES]
YOU'RE TIRED.
GO TO SLEEP.
WELL, I MUST ADMIT
THE SENSOR READINGS
SEEM TOO GOOD.
HUMAN READINGS, YES,
BUT NOT A SINGLE
PHYSICAL FLAW.
TOTALLY PERFECT BODY.
IF AN ALIEN
NEEDED A BODY...
HE MIGHT BE INCLINED
TO PREPARE A PERFECT
ONE, CAPTAIN.
BUT THEN AGAIN...
HE MAY BE
TELLING THE TRUTH.
GENTLEMEN, I NEED PROOF.
ALL YOU'RE TELLING ME
IS THAT ON THE ONE HAND
HE MAY BE LYING
AND ON THE OTHER--
On intercom:
SECURITY ALERT.
ALL-DECKS ALERT.
PRISONER HAS ESCAPED.
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
INFORM US--
Uhura: CAPTAIN,
TRANSPORTER CIRCUITS
SHOW SOMEONE
PREPARING
TO BEAM DOWN.
TRY TO OVERRIDE.
SHUT IT OFF!
[ALARM SOUNDS]
[MEOW]
I KNOW, ISIS.
BUT WE'LL BE GONE
BEFORE THEY GET HERE.
[MEOW MEOW]
YOU'RE RIGHT, ISIS.
IT IS PRIMITIVE.
IT'S INCREDIBLE
THAT PEOPLE
CAN EXIST LIKE THIS.
AT LEAST WE WON'T
HAVE TO--
NOT FOR LONG.
COMPUTER ON.
SPECIFY LOCATIONS
OF AGENTS 201 AND 347.
IDENTIFY SELF.
SIMPLY CHECK
MY VOICE PATTERN.
YOU'LL
FIND ME LISTED
AS SUPERVISOR 194.
CODE NAME GARY SEVEN.
VOICE PATTERN MATCHES,
BUT I HAVE NO LISTING
OF A GARY SEVEN
ASSIGNED THIS PLANET.
COMPUTER, I AM
A CLASS-1 SUPERVISOR.
YOU ARE ORDERED
TO OVERRIDE
PREVIOUS INSTRUCTIONS
AND ANSWER MY QUESTION.
I AM A BETA-5 COMPUTER
CAPABLE OF
ANALYTICAL DECISIONS.
PLEASE CONFIRM IDENTITY
AS SUPERVISOR
BY DESCRIBING
NATURE OF AGENTS
AND MISSION HERE.
COMPUTER,
I CAUTION YOU.
I HAVE LITTLE LOVE
FOR BETA-5 SNOBBERY.
OVERRIDE.
ALL RIGHT.
AGENTS ARE MALE
AND FEMALE,
DESCENDANTS
OF HUMAN ANCESTORS
TAKEN FROM EARTH
APPROXIMATELY
6,000 YEARS AGO.
THEY'RE THE PRODUCT
OF GENERATIONS
OF TRAINING
FOR THIS MISSION.
PROBLEM--EARTH TECHNOLOGY
AND SCIENCE
HAVE PROGRESSED FASTER
THAN POLITICAL
AND SOCIAL KNOWLEDGE.
PURPOSE OF MISSION--
TO PREVENT
EARTH'S CIVILIZATION
FROM DESTROYING ITSELF
BEFORE IT CAN MATURE
INTO A PEACEFUL SOCIETY.
INCOMPLETE.
NOT SUFFICIENT.
LOCATION OF AGENTS
UNREPORTED
FOR THREE DAYS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
SAY SO IN THE FIRST PLACE?
NO, DON'T ANSWER THAT.
SIMPLY BEGIN SEARCH
IMMEDIATELY.
RECHECK ALL NEWS
BROADCASTS,
DECODE ANY GOVERNMENT
INTERCEPTED MESSAGE--
I AM AWARE OF PROPER
SEARCH PROCEDURES, 194.
WE CAN ESTIMATE ONLY
WITHIN 1,000 METERS OR SO
WHERE HE BEAMED DOWN, CAPTAIN.
IF WE BEAM DOWN,
CAN YOU COMPARE
OUR POSITION WITH
HIS CONTROL SETTING?
AYE.
FOLLOWING HIM DOWN
IS A MAJOR RISK,
CAPTAIN.
IF WE OURSELVES
DO ANYTHING THAT
CHANGES HISTORY--
I'M AWARE OF THAT.
BUT I MUST KNOW
IF HE'S LYING.
AND WE CAN'T ANSWER THAT
SITTING UP HERE.
HAVE SHIP'S STORES
PREPARE THE PROPER
COSTUMES.
STAND BY
TO BEAM US DOWN.
IN RESPONSE
TO NUCLEAR WARHEAD
PLACED IN SUBORBIT
BY OTHER MAJOR POWER,
UNITED STATES TODAY
LAUNCHING SUBORBITAL PLATFORM
WITH MULTI-WARHEAD
CAPACITY.
PURPOSE--TO MAINTAIN
BALANCE OF POWER.
THAT'S THE SAME
KIND OF NONSENSE
THAT ALMOST DESTROYED
PLANET OMICRON IV.
ANALYSIS CORRECT.
EARTH'S SITUATION,
SIMILAR.
MISSION OF AGENTS
201 AND 347--
SET MALFUNCTION
ON UNITED STATES ROCKET.
PROGRESS OF MISSION--
HAS THE ROCKET
BEEN SET TO MALFUNCTION?
NEGATIVE.
NO PROGRESS.
HOW MUCH TIME
BEFORE LAUNCH?
EXACTLY 1 HOUR,
27 MINUTES,
12 SECONDS.
[MEOW MEOW]
COMPUTER,
RECORD THE FOLLOWING.
UNLESS AGENTS ARE
FOUND IMMEDIATELY,
I MUST UNDERTAKE
THEIR MISSION.
SCOTTY, LOCK IN
ON OUR POSITION.
LEAD US TO HIM.
LOCKED IN. PROCEED
195 DEGREES TRUE.
[BABY CRIES]
HELLO?
ANYBODY HERE?
LOOKS LIKE YOUR
LUCKY DAY, ROBERTA.
THEY CAN'T DOCK YOU
IF THEY DON'T KNOW
YOU'RE LATE.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
OH, THE SUBWAY
GOT STALLED--
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN
FOR THE PAST
THREE DAYS?
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
WHY SHOULD I
TELL YOU?
WHO ARE YOU, ANYWAY?
WHERE'S 347?
WITH 348?
201, CODE RESPONSES
ARE NOT NECESSARY.
LISTEN...FRIEND...
MAYBE I JUST BETTER
CALL THE POLICE
RIGHT NOW, HUH?
SIT DOWN.
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU ARE?
I SAID, SIT DOWN.
O.K. I WILL.
I'LL SAY
ONE THING FOR YOU.
YOU PLAY YOUR ROLE WELL.
HOWEVER, THAT IS
NO LONGER NECESSARY.
I AM SUPERVISOR 194,
CODE NAME GARY SEVEN.
I NEED A COMPLETE
REPORT--
REPORT.
YES, A REPORT--
EVERYTHING
YOU HAVE DONE
FOR THE PAST THREE
EARTH DAYS.
OH.
EVERYTHING I'VE DONE?
EVERYTHING
YOU'VE DONE.
WELL...O.K.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
NOT WITH YOUR
FINGERS.
[BEEP BEEP]
WELL, HOW DO YOU
EXPECT ME TO TYPE,
WITH MY NOSE?
DID YOU SEE THAT?
THE MACHINE TYPED
EVERYTHING I...
IT'S TYPING
EVERYTHING I'M SAYING!
STOP IT.
STOP IT!
[BEEP BEEP]
O.K. THAT DOES IT.
I QUIT!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE. YOU'RE--
I'M QUITTING
RIGHT NOW!
YOU'RE NOT ACTING,
ARE YOU?
ACTING? I'M LEAVING.
GOOD-BYE.
[ELECTRONIC TONES]
HEY.
HEY!
TIE INTO COMPUTER.
COMPUTER ON.
SCAN AND IDENTIFY
FEMALE PRESENT.
ROBERTA LINCOLN.
HUMAN.
PROFESSION--SECRETARY.
EMPLOYED BY 347 AND 201.
DESCRIPTION--
AGE 20, 5'7",
120 POUNDS.
HAIR PRESENTLY TINTED
HONEY BLONDE.
ALTHOUGH BEHAVIOR
APPEARS ERRATIC,
POSSESSES HIGH I.Q.
BIRTHMARKS--
HEY.
SMALL MOLE
ON LEFT SHOULDER.
SOMEWHAT LARGER
STAR-SHAPED MARK ON HER--
HEY, WATCH IT!
O.K., I'LL BITE.
WHAT IS IT?
MISS LINCOLN...
MISS LINCOLN, UM...
WHAT...KIND OF WORK
DID YOUR EMPLOYERS
SAY THEY WERE
DOING HERE?
RESEARCH FOR A NEW
ENCYCLOPEDIA?
NO?
NO.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN GO.
OF COURSE,
IF YOU DO,
YOU WON'T BE
HELPING
YOUR COUNTRY.
UNLESS YOU DON'T
CARE ABOUT THAT.
SURE, I CARE.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK I AM?
I DON'T KNOW,
MISS LINCOLN,
WHAT YOU ARE,
NOT YET.
ALL I KNOW IS
THAT MY INCOMPETENCE
HAS MADE YOU AWARE
OF SOME VERY
SECRET DEVICES
THAT ARE VITAL
TO THE SECURITY
OF THIS NATION.
OH. WELL, WHAT ARE
YOU GUYS AROUND
HERE, ANYWAY? FBI?
LIKE SOME KIND
OF GOVERNMENT
AGENTS, HUH?
VERY GROOVY.
[MEOW]
THANK YOU, ISIS.
I'LL BE...
RIGHT IN.
IT'S A TRAINED CAT,
JUST LIKE, UH...
GUARD DOGS,
THAT KIND OF THING.
YEAH?
DON'T LET
ANYBODY IN HERE.
I'LL BE BUSY.
O.K.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
SCOTTY, TRIANGULATE
ON THIS LOCATION.
CORRELATED.
READINGS INDICATE
A GREATER ALTITUDE...
APPROXIMATELY...
30 METERS HIGHER, SIR.
OUT.
OCCURRENCE--
AUTOMOBILE ACCIDENT.
LOCATION--HIGHWAY 949,
10 MILES NORTH
OF McKINLEY ROCKET BASE.
AGENTS 347 AND 201
WERE KILLED INSTANTLY.
THAT JUST DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE...
FOR THEM TO DIE
IN SOMETHING
AS USELESS
AS AN AUTOMOBILE
ACCIDENT.
ARE THE FACTS
VERIFIED?
VERIFIED.
DESCRIPTIONS OF BODIES
ARE EXACT.
GO AHEAD, SCOTTY.
PROCEED 5 METERS,
247 DEGREES TRUE.
[DING DONG]
COMPUTER OFF.
WHERE'S MR. SEVEN?
OH. I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
LISTEN, YOU GUYS
CAN'T COME IN HERE.
WHERE'S
MR. SEVEN?
YOU CAN'T COME
IN HERE. NOW, GET OUT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING? THIS IS
A GOVERNMENT OFFICE.
YOU CAN'T COME IN HERE.
NEITHER ONE OF YOU
CAN COME IN HERE.
Kirk: MR. SEVEN.
Spock:
IN HERE, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS AGAINST
THE RULES. WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
YOU WANT ME TO--
SEND THE POLICE. 811
EAST 68th STREET,
APARTMENT 12B.
GIVE ME THE PHONE.
NO, GET YOUR HANDS
OFF OF ME,
YOU BIG JERK!
WHO DO YOU
THINK YOU ARE?
LET GO OF ME!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING,
YOU BIG JERK?
WHAT'S THE BIG IDEA?
MR. SEVEN,
MR. SEVEN, HELP!
HELP!
LET GO OF ME!
STOP IT!
DON'T GO IN!
WHAT'S THE BIG IDEA?
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF OF ME!
I MEAN IT!
WHAT ARE YOU?
[ALARM SOUNDS]
P.A.: ATTENTION.
STAND BY
FOR LAUNCH AREA CLEARANCE.
IT IS NOW
60 MINUTES TO LAUNCH.
"T" MINUS 60
AND COUNTING.
WHERE'S MR. SEVEN?
I'M WARNING YOU
I'VE ALREADY CALLED
THE POLICE.
PLANS TO McKINLEY
ROCKET BASE.
THERE IT IS, CHARLEY.
OPEN UP IN THERE.
POLICE.
[STIFLED SCREAM]
OPEN UP IN THERE!
IT'S THE POLICE!
WIDE SCAN, SCOTTY.
WE'LL BE MOVING.
SPOCK,
IN HERE.
SPOCK!
IN THERE!
NOW, SCOTTY!
WHAT'S GOING
ON HERE?
REVERSE AND ENERGIZE.
CHARLEY...
P.A.: ATTENTION.
IT IS NOW 50 MINUTES
TO LAUNCH.
"T" MINUS 50
AND COUNTING.
ALL SYSTEMS CLEAR.
STANDING BY
FOR INSPECTION
OF LAUNCH PAD.
YOU!
SPEAK TO YOU
A MOMENT?
YEAH, SURE, SARGE.
THERE IT IS.
I'LL HAVE TO CONFIRM
THIS, COLONEL.
ALL RIGHT.
OH. UH, JUST PUT
THE CAT DOWN
AND KEEP YOUR HANDS
AT YOUR SIDE.
ALL RIGHT.
GIVE ME SECURITY.
IDENTIFICATION CHECK.
BE CAREFUL, ISIS.
DON'T GET STEPPED ON.
UH, YEAH, SECURITY?
[REOW REOW]
UH, SECURITY,
THIS IS SERGEANT LIPTON,
AND WE'RE
ALL STRAIGHTENED OUT
DOWN HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD-BYE.
ALL RIGHT, SERGEANT.
NOW LET'S JUST TURN
RIGHT AROUND,
AND WE'RE GOING
TO WALK THIS WAY.
YOU JUST SIT RIGHT DOWN
RIGHT THERE
AND HAVE A LITTLE NAP.
P.A.: ATTENTION. IT IS NOW
45 MINUTES TO LAUNCH.
"T" MINUS 45
AND COUNTING.
ALL SYSTEMS CLEAR.
STAND BY FOR INSPECTION
OF LAUNCH PAD.
HEADING FOR THE GANTRY.
SOUND ALERT.
[ALERT SOUNDS]
ATTENTION. FIRST ALERT.
FIRST ALERT.
BEGIN CLEARING
GANTRY AREA.
CLEAR LAUNCH PAD.
SAFETY GROUP,
ALL SYSTEMS
CONTINUE TO GREEN.
REPEAT--ALL SYSTEMS
STILL GREEN.
STANDING BY FOR INSPECTION
OF LAUNCH PAD.
THERE'S AN OLD STYLE
WEATHER SATELLITE
IN ORBIT BELOW US.
IF I COULD
BOUNCE OFF IT,
I COULD GET
SOME GOOD VIEWS.
I'VE GOT IT.
I COULD GET EVEN CLOSER.
IF I COULD SPOT HIM,
I COULD LOCK ON
AND BEAM HIM UP.
CHANCES ARE
HE'S OUT OF SIGHT
INSIDE THE ROCKET GANTRY
OR AT ONE OF
THE CONTROL CENTERS.
LAUNCH IS IN 40 MINUTES.
STAND BY
TO BEAM US DOWN.
CONTINUE VISUAL SCAN.
[KLAXON SOUNDS]
ATTENTION.
STAND BY FOR LAUNCH AREA
CLEARANCES.
RANGE SAFETY VERIFIED.
LAUNCH DIRECTOR
NOW EN ROUTE
ROCKET GANTRY
TO CONFIRM
LAUNCH PAD CLEAR.
GROUND STATIONS
3, 4, AND 11, STAND BY
FOR CONFIRMATION.
REPEAT--STAND BY
FOR LAUNCH AREA CLEARANCE.
HI, JACK.
MR. CROMWELL.
LAUNCH DIRECTOR
AT GANTRY.
BEGINNING FINAL CHECK.
ATTENTION.
IT IS NOW 35 MINUTES
TO LAUNCH.
"T" MINUS 35 MINUTES
AND COUNTING.
CANARY ISLANDS CONFIRMING.
THEY ARE GO FOR THE LAUNCH.
ALL GROUND STATIONS
CONFIRM GO.
LOCK THE ELEVATOR
AT THE TOP,
LIEUTENANT.
TIME TO GET
OUT OF HERE.
ATTENTION.
CLEAR LAUNCH PAD.
REPEAT--CLEAR LAUNCH PAD
AT GANTRY.
FREEZE!
ONE MOVE,
AND YOU'VE BOTH HAD IT.
INTRUDER ALERT.
SECURITY
TO LAUNCH DIRECTOR.
WE HAVE UNIDENTIFIED
INTRUDERS--MALES, A PAIR.
WE WANT TO DELAY
COUNTDOWN.
ALL RIGHT. DON'T ANSWER.
BUT YOU CAN TELL HIM I QUIT.
AND YOU CAN TELL HIM
I PROMISE NOT TO TELL
ANYBODY ANYTHING.
HE'S SAFE, AND YOU'RE SAFE,
MY LITTLE GREEN FRIEND.
SAME TO YOU.
OH...
ATTENTION.
20 MINUTES TO LAUNCH.
"T" MINUS 20 MINUTES
AND COUNTING.
ALL SYSTEMS,
CONTINUE GREEN.
REPEAT--ALL SYSTEMS
STILL GREEN.
[PURRING]
YES, THANK YOU.
I KNOW HOW TO OPEN IT.
[MEOW]
I KNOW
THERE'S NOT MUCH TIME.
THESE WERE ALL
THEY WERE CARRYING.
"T" MINUS 15 MINUTES
AND COUNTING.
YOU'VE GOT A CHANCE,
AND I'LL OFFER IT
ONLY THIS ONCE.
THE SLIGHTEST
POSSIBLE CHARGES
WILL BE BROUGHT
AGAINST YOU
IF YOU
IDENTIFY YOURSELVES
AND TELL US
WHY YOU'RE HERE.
DELAY COUNTDOWN.
Man: NO SIGN
OF TROUBLE
ON MY BOARDS.
LAUNCH DIRECTOR,
CONFIRM STATUS
ALL SYSTEMS.
CONTROL TO LAUNCH DIRECTOR
CONFIRMING.
STATUS BOARD INDICATES
ALL IS WELL.
SPACE FLIGHT CONDITIONS
MEASURE OUT AS PLANNED.
CONTINUE COUNTDOWN.
NO COUNTDOWN DELAY.
REPEAT--NO DELAY.
ALL SYSTEMS ARE GREEN AND GO.
ALL SYSTEMS ARE GO.
"T" MINUS 14 AND COUNTING.
[MEOW]
MEOW? YOU ARE NERVOUS,
AREN'T YOU, DOLL?
[MEOW]
ALL RIGHT.
I'M GOING AS FAST
AS I CAN.
"T" MINUS 13 MINUTES
AND COUNTING.
STATUS BOARD LOOKS GOOD.
STAGES LOOK GOOD.
ALL SYSTEMS GO.
STATUS BOARD SAYS GO.
SECURITY,
SEND TWO MEN UP HERE
RIGHT AWAY.
"T" MINUS EIGHT MINUTES
AND COUNTING.
ALL SYSTEMS GO.
STATUS BOARD GO.
NO!
STAND BY.
I'M GONNA BEAM HIM UP.
I HAD HIM,
BUT SOMETHING
YANKED HIM AWAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I WASN'T FINISHED.
I'M SORRY. I JUST
TOUCHED THAT BUTTON,
RIGHT THERE. AND THEN WOW!
MUST HAVE INTERCEPTED
THE "ENTERPRISE"
TRYING
TO BEAM ME ON-BOARD.
COMPUTER ON.
LOCK INTO
LAUNCH SITE SCAN.
Computer:
ONE MINUTE TO LAUNCH.
OH, MY GOSH!
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
SUPPLEMENTAL.
SPOCK AND I IN CUSTODY.
EVEN IF WE TALKED,
THEY WOULDN'T BELIEVE US.
WE'RE POWERLESS
TO STOP MR. SEVEN
OR PREVENT THE LAUNCH
OR EVEN BE CERTAIN
IF WE SHOULD.
I HAVE NEVER FELT
SO HELPLESS.
Computer:
30 SECONDS TO LAUNCH.
LOOK, HEY, I MEAN, LIKE,
NOT EVEN THE CIA
COULD DO ALL THIS.
P.A.: "T" MINUS 20 SECONDS.
MARK.
STAGES REPORTING
READY FOR LAUNCH.
AUTOMATIC SEQUENCES ON.
SHE'S COMPLETELY
AUTOMATIC NOW.
Computer: 15 SECONDS
TO LAUNCH.
10 SECONDS.
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...2...
1.
IGNITION.
WE HAVE IGNITION.
ALTITUDE--1,000 FEET.
ALL GOOD.
ALL AS PLANNED.
TRAJECTORY NOMINAL.
Computer: ROCKET
PASSING 20-MILE MARK
AND ACCELERATING.
COMPUTER, ADJUSTMENTS
AT THE ROCKET BASE
WERE NOT COMPLETED.
CAN I STILL TAKE OVER
THE ROCKET AS PLANNED?
ROCKET CONTROL POSSIBLE
WITH EXCEIVER CIRCUITS
OPERATED MANUALLY.
EXCEIVER ON MANUAL.
LOCK INTO
FLIGHT TELEMETRY.
VISUAL OFF.
[MEOW]
ROBERTA, PLEASE
DON'T TRY TO LEAVE.
YOU'LL FIND
ALL THE DOORS LOCKED.
[MEOW MEOW]
ARE YOU JEALOUS, ISIS?
MOST UNBECOMING.
ROCKET ALTITUDE
NOW 100 MILES.
STANDING BY
TO BEGIN MALFUNCTION
AS PLANNED.
BEGIN MALFUNCTION
OF THIRD STAGE.
EXCEIVER SETTING NOW
90.08.
SECOND STAGE
READY TO DETACH.
VISUAL ON.
SECOND STAGE DETACHING.
THIRD STAGE IGNITING.
BEGIN MALFUNCTION.
TAKE IT OFF COURSE.
MALFUNCTION SETTING CORRECT.
ROCKET VEERING
FROM PLANNED COURSE.
GIVE ME
THE READINGS, FAST.
WHAT IS IT?
MALFUNCTION.
ROCKET IS DEVIATING
FROM PROGRAMMED FLIGHT PATH.
SAFETY,
STAND BY TO DESTRUCT.
CONTINUING DEVIATION
FROM FLIGHT PATH.
REPEAT--DEVIATION CONFIRMED
AND INCREASING.
TELEMETRY--
CONTROL TRANSMITTER SYSTEMS
TIE IN.
ALL SYSTEMS TIE IN.
REPORT.
ARM THE WARHEAD.
Computer: ACCOMPLISHED.
NUCLEAR WARHEAD NOW ARMED.
SET EXCEIVER 91.218.
EXCEIVER 91.218.
[VOICES
IN VARIOUS LANGUAGES]
SCOTT HERE.
SENSOR SHOWS
THAT THE ROCKET
HAS ARMED ITSELF,
MR. SCOTT.
COMPUTERS INDICATE
AN IMPACT
SOMEWHERE IN THE HEART
OF THE EURASIAN
CONTINENT.
THERE'S STILL TIME TO
ENTER CLOSE ORBIT DESTROY
IT WITH OUR PHASERS, SIR.
THEY'RE BEGINNING
TO WORRY DOWN
ON EARTH, MR. SCOTT.
I'M GETTING
MILITARY ALERTS
FROM THE MAJOR
POWERS.
I'VE GOT TO RISK
CALLING THE CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN A CHANNEL.
AYE, AYE.
WARHEAD STATUS CONFIRMED.
SHE'S ARMED HERSELF
SOMEHOW.
REPEAT--THIS BIRD
IS ARMED.
THE WARHEAD'S ALIVE.
ALL BOARDS REPORT STATUS.
STAND BY ON DESTRUCT.
STAND BY TO TRANSMIT
DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
HOW COULD THE WARHEAD
ARM ITSELF?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE CAN DESTROY IT,
OF COURSE.
IF WE CAN'T,
WE'RE GONNA LAND AN H-BOMB
ON SOMEBODY SOMEWHERE.
READY ON DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
DESTRUCT.
TRANSMIT DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
GET BACK OVER THERE.
LOOK, I'M SORRY,
BUT LIKE YOU ASKED ME,
I DO CARE
ABOUT MY COUNTRY,
AND YOU CAN'T BE CIA.
Computer: ORBITAL
PLATFORM SEPARATING.
HOLD IT!
COMPUTER, ROCKET STATUS.
HOLD IT, MR. SEVEN.
I'M TELLING YOU,
YOU'RE THROUGH
MONKEYING AROUND WITH
MY COUNTRY'S ROCKET.
WARHEAD STILL ARMED.
SIX MINUTES TO IMPACT.
HOLD IT!
JUST DON'T MOVE!
YOU DID ENOUGH ALREADY!
ROBERTA, YOU'VE
GOT TO LET ME FINISH
WHAT I'VE STARTED,
OR IN SIX MINUTES,
WORLD WAR III BEGINS.
FLIGHT PATH CONTINUING
ON TARGET.
DESTRUCT IS FOULED UP
SOMEHOW, FLIGHT CONTROL.
SHE'S COMING DOWN
FULLY ARMED.
SHE'LL GO OFF ON IMPACT.
WHAT? TRY AGAIN!
BOOST THE SIGNAL!
BOOSTING SIGNAL.
FLIGHT CONTROL,
WE HAVE BOOSTED
DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
REPEAT--DESTRUCT SIGNAL
AT MAXIMUM BOOST.
Scotty:
CAPTAIN, CAN YOU READ ME?
I WAS BEAMING UP MR. SEVEN,
AND SOMETHING YANKED HIM
AWAY FROM ME.
HELLO? HELLO.
COME IN. WHO ARE YOU...
HERE. LET ME
HELP YOU, SERGEANT.
IT'S OPERATED
FROM THIS DIAL HERE.
WE'RE GETTING
NO RESPONSE.
MAKE ABSOLUTELY CERTAIN.
CHECK EVERYTHING AGAIN.
TRACKING STATIONS
REPORT NO RESPONSE
ON DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
SCOTTY, BEAM US DIRECTLY
TO SEVEN'S APARTMENT.
AUXILIARY TRANSMITTERS,
CHECK OUT FLIGHT CONTROL.
SHE HASN'T
DESTRUCTED HERSELF.
REPEAT--
DESTRUCT IS NOT WORKING.
SHE'S STILL UP THERE.
DO YOU READ?
DESCENDING AND ARMED.
SHE'LL GO OFF ON IMPACT.
BERMUDA GROUND STATION
REPORTS SHE'S STILL
UP THERE.
SOUTH AFRICA
GROUND STATION
REPORTS NO RESPONSE
ON BOOSTER
DESTRUCT SIGNAL.
GET ME THE PRESIDENT.
Computer:
ROCKET DESCENDING
AND ACCELERATING.
DO YOU HAVE FURTHER
INSTRUCTIONS, 194?
ROBERTA, YOU'VE GOT
TO BELIEVE ME.
A TRULY ADVANCED PLANET
WOULDN'T USE FORCE.
THEY WOULDN'T COME HERE
IN STRANGE ALIEN FORMS.
THE BEST OF ALL
POSSIBLE METHODS
WOULD BE
TO TAKE HUMAN BEINGS
TO THEIR WORLD,
TRAIN THEM
FOR GENERATIONS
UNTIL
THEY'RE NEEDED HERE.
MR. SEVEN, I WANT
TO BELIEVE YOU. I DO.
I MEAN, I KNOW THIS
WORLD NEEDS HELP.
THAT'S WHY SOME
OF MY GENERATION ARE
KIND OF CRAZY AND REBELS,
YOU KNOW? WE WONDER IF
WE'RE GONNA BE
ALIVE WHEN WE'RE 30.
Computer:
TWO MINUTES TO IMPACT.
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE,
MR. SEVEN.
OH, NO.
SPOCK,
YOU'RE THE EXPERT.
CAN YOU DETONATE
THE WARHEAD FROM THIS COMPUTER?
I CAN TRY,
CAPTAIN.
Computer:
ALTITUDE--550 MILES.
[STATIC]
CAPTAIN, I WANT THAT
WARHEAD DETONATED, TOO.
UNLESS I DO IT
AT LEAST 100 MILES
ABOVE GROUND
JUST BARELY IN TIME
TO FRIGHTEN THEM OUT OF
THIS ARMS RACE--
Scotty:
CAPTAIN, MONITORS SHOW
ALL MAJOR POWERS
ON FULL MISSILE ALERT.
RETALIATORY STRIKE ORDERED
ON WARHEAD IMPACT.
Computer:
ALTITUDE--450 MILES.
SPOCK.
I CAN ESTIMATE
SOME OF THIS, CAPTAIN,
BUT WITHOUT MORE TIME...
CAPTAIN, HE CAN ONLY GUESS.
WILL YOU PLEASE
LET ME DO MY JOB?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOUR JOB IS.
YOU MAY SET
THOSE CONTROLS
SO WE CAN'T DETONATE
THAT WARHEAD.
LISTEN, YOU,
GET AWAY FROM HIM!
ROBERTA,
BE CAREFUL.
THE SERVO
IS SET TO KILL.
Computer:
ALTITUDE--400 MILES.
THERE ARE ONLY SECONDS.
I'LL NEED TIME
TO SET IT.
PLEASE. HE'S TELLING
THE TRUTH.
Computer:
55 SECONDS TO IMPACT.
SPOCK,
IF YOU CAN'T HANDLE IT,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO TRUST HIM.
IT IS DIFFICULT
TO KNOW WHICH IS
BEST, CAPTAIN.
Computer:
40 SECONDS TO IMPACT.
WITHOUT FACTS,
THE DECISION CANNOT
BE MADE LOGICALLY.
YOU MUST RELY
ON YOUR HUMAN
INTUITION.
Computer:
ALTITUDE--300 MILES.
DESCENDING
AND ACCELERATING...
GO.
COMPUTER,
GO TO VISUAL.
COUNT BY 10s.
Computer:
190 MILES.
180 MILES.
170 MILES.
160 MILES.
150...
140...
130...
120...
Computer:
DETONATION--104 MILES.
AND IN SPITE
OF THE ACCIDENTAL
INTERFERENCE WITH HISTORY
BY THE EARTHSHIP
FROM THE FUTURE...
THE MISSION
WAS COMPLETED.
CORRECTION, MR. SEVEN.
IT APPEARS
WE DID NOT INTERFERE.
RATHER, THE "ENTERPRISE"
WAS SIMPLY PART OF WHAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN
ON THIS DAY IN 1968.
AS OUR RECORD TAPES
SHOW, ALTHOUGH NEVER
GENERALLY REVEALED,
THAT ON THIS DATE,
A MALFUNCTIONING
SUBORBITAL WARHEAD
WAS EXPLODED
EXACTLY 104 MILES
ABOVE THE EARTH.
SO EVERYTHING HAPPENED
EXACTLY THE WAY IT WAS
SUPPOSED TO.
Spock: AND YOU'LL BE
PLEASED OUR RECORDS SHOW
THAT IT RESULTED
IN A NEW AND STRONGER
INTERNATIONAL AGREEMENT
AGAINST THE USE
OF SUCH WEAPONS.
WOULD YOU MIND
TELLING ME
WHO THAT IS?
THAT, MISS LINCOLN,
IS SIMPLY MY CAT.
YOUR CAT?
WHAT ELSE
DO YOUR RECORD
TAPES SHOW?
I'M AFRAID
WE CAN'T REVEAL
EVERYTHING WE KNOW,
MR. SEVEN.
CAPTAIN, WE COULD SAY
THAT MR. SEVEN
AND MISS LINCOLN
HAVE SOME
INTERESTING EXPERIENCES
IN STORE FOR THEM.
YES, I THINK WE
COULD SAY THAT.
TWO TO BEAM UP,
SCOTTY.
LIVE LONG AND PROSPER,
MR. SEVEN.
SAME TO YOU,
MISS LINCOLN.
ENERGIZE.