[SIREN]
PHASER BANKS
STANDING BY, SIR.
RANGE,
43,000 AND CLOSING.
WHAT DO YOU READ,
MR. SPOCK?
CONFIGURATION,
UNIDENTIFIED.
ION PROPULSION,
HIGH VELOCITY,
THOUGH OF
A UNIQUE TECHNOLOGY.
ANY CONTACT,
LIEUTENANT?
HAILING ON
ALL FREQUENCIES.
ALL LANGUAGES
HAVE BEEN ATTEMPTED.
NO RESPONSE.
NOW USING STANDARD
INTERSTELLAR SYMBOLS.
KEEP TRYING.
AYE, SIR.
MAGNIFICATION 10,
MR. CHEKOV.
AYE, SIR.
38,000 AND CLOSING.
WELL, SCOTTY?
IT BEATS ME.
BUT ISN'T SHE A BEAUTY?
INTERESTING DESIGN.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE HER.
AND ION PROPULSION
AT THAT.
THEY COULD TEACH US
A THING OR TWO.
LIFE FORMS,
MR. SPOCK?
ONE.
HUMANOID OR SIMILAR.
LOW LEVEL OF ACTIVITY.
LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS
FUNCTIONING.
INTERIOR ATMOSPHERE.
CONVENTIONAL
NITROGEN OXYGEN.
[BEEP BEEP BEEP]
INSTRUMENTS INDICATE
A TRANSFERAL BEAM
EMANATING FROM THE AREA
OF THE HUMANOID LIFE FORM.
DIRECTED AT WHAT?
DIRECTED AT THE BRIDGE
OF THE ENTERPRISE, CAPTAIN.
SECURITY GUARD.
SECURITY GUARD
TO THE BRIDGE.
I'M CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
THIS IS THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HELM STATUS, MR. SULU.
NO CHANGE FROM
LAST READING, SIR.
CONDITION REPORTS
FROM ALL DECKS, LIEUTENANT.
AYE, SIR.
SPOCK. WHERE'S SPOCK?
JIM! JIM!
YES, WHAT IS IT?
BETTER COME DOWN TO SICK BAY
RIGHT NOW.
ALL RIGHT.
ON MY WAY.
DECK FIVE,
PERSONNEL, NO DAMAGE.
NOW.
FUNCTIONING.
THANK GOD.
SPOCK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I FOUND HIM
ON THE TABLE.
LIKE THIS?
NO, NOT LIKE THIS.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'VE GOT HIM
ON COMPLETE
LIFE SUPPORT.
WAS HE DEAD?
HE WAS WORSE THAN DEAD.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
JIM--
COME ON, BONES,
WHAT'S THE MYSTERY?
HIS BRAIN IS GONE.
IT'S BEEN REMOVED
SURGICALLY.
HOW COULD HE SURVIVE?
IT'S THE GREATEST
TECHNICAL JOB
I'VE EVER SEEN.
EVERY NERVE ENDING
IN THE BRAIN
MUST'VE BEEN
NEATLY SEALED.
NOTHING RIPPED,
NOTHING TORN,
NO BLEEDING.
IT'S A MEDICAL MIRACLE.
IF HIS BRAIN
IS MISSING...
THEN SPOCK IS DYING.
NO.
THAT INCREDIBLE
VULCAN PHYSIQUE
HUNG ON UNTIL
THE LIFE SUPPORT CYCLE
TOOK OVER.
HIS BODY LIVES,
THE AUTONOMIC FUNCTIONS
CONTINUE...
BUT THERE IS NO MIND.
THAT GIRL.
AYE.
WHAT GIRL?
FROM THAT SHIP.
SHE TOOK IT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY...
OR WHERE...
BUT SHE MUST'VE
TAKEN IT.
BONES, HOW LONG CAN YOU
KEEP HIM FUNCTIONING.
I CAN'T GIVE YOU
ANY GUARANTEE.
THAT'S NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
DOCTOR.
IF IT HAPPENED
TO ANY OF US,
I'D SAY INDEFINITELY.
BUT VULCAN PHYSIOLOGY
LIMITS WHAT I CAN DO.
SPOCK'S BODY
IS MUCH MORE DEPENDENT
ON THAT TREMENDOUS BRAIN
FOR LIFE SUPPORT.
THEN WE'LL HAVE TO
TAKE HIM WITH US.
TAKE HIM WHERE?
IN SEARCH OF HIS BRAIN,
DOCTOR.
FROM WHAT YOU SAY,
THE MOMENT WE FIND IT,
WE MUST RESTORE IT
TO HIS BODY,
OR WE LOSE HIM.
JIM, WHERE ARE YOU
GOING TO LOOK
IN THIS
WHOLE GALAXY?
WHERE ARE YOU
GOING TO LOOK
FOR SPOCK'S BRAIN?
HOW ARE YOU
GOING TO FIND IT?
I'LL FIND IT.
EVEN IF YOU DO,
I CAN'T RESTORE IT.
I DON'T HAVE
THE MEDICAL
TECHNIQUE.
IT WAS TAKEN OUT.
IT CAN BE PUT BACK IN.
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW.
THE THIEF THAT TOOK IT
HAS THE KNOWLEDGE.
I'LL FORCE IT
OUT OF HER.
IF YOU DON'T FIND IT
IN 24 HOURS,
YOU BETTER FORGET
THE WHOLE THING, JIM.
YOU AND SCOTTY...
HAVE SPOCK READY.
I'VE GOT IT AGAIN.
AN ION TRAIL.
WHERE DOES
THE TRAIL LEAD,
MR. CHEKOV?
SYSTEM
SIGMA DRACONIS.
LOCK ON, MR. SULU.
MAXIMUM SPEED.
WARP 6.
NO QUESTION
ABOUT THE TRAIL?
NO MISTAKE, SIR.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5431.4
FOR 15 HOURS
AND 20 MINUTES
WE HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING
THE ION TRAIL
OF THE SPACE SHIP
THAT HAS SPOCK'S BRAIN.
TIME LEFT TO US--
8 HOURS AND 40 MINUTES.
CAPTAIN,
I'VE LOST THE TRAIL.
ALL SCANNERS,
EXTREME SWEEP.
AYE, SIR.
WELL?
NOTHING, SIR.
NO SIGNAL AT ALL,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S GONE, SIR.
A SUDDEN DEACTION SHIFT.
WE'VE LOST HER TRAIL,
BUT SHE WENT
INTO THAT SYSTEM.
MR. CHEKOV,
PUT A SCHEMATIC OF SIGMA
DRACONIS ON THE SCREEN.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
READOUT, MR. CHEKOV.
SUN, SPECTRAL TYPE,
GAMMA 9,
NINE PLANETS,
THREE OF THEM,
CLASS "M"
POSSESSING
SAPIENT LIFE
ACCORDING TO REPORTS
AND LONG RANGE
SCANNING.
SHE WAS BREATHING OUR AIR.
SHE MUST'VE GONE
TO ONE OF THEM.
SHOW US THE THREE
CLASS "M" PLANETS.
THE ONE ON THE LEFT,
NUMBER 3,
RATES LETTER "B"
ON THE INDUSTRIAL SCALE.
EARTH EQUIVALENT
APPROXIMATELY...
1485.
YES, SIR.
SECOND PLANET CLASS "M,"
NUMBER 4,
RATES LETTER "G."
YEAR 2030.
BUT THAT SHIP, CAPTAIN,
EITHER IT WAS
MANY YEARS AHEAD OF US
OR IT WAS THE MOST INCREDIBLE
DESIGN FLUKE IN HISTORY.
THIRD CLASS "M" PLANET,
MR. CHEKOV.
NUMBER 6.
NO SIGN OF
INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT.
AT LAST REPORT,
IN A GLACIAL AGE.
SAPIENT LIFE PLENTIFUL,
BUT ON A MOST
PRIMITIVE LEVEL.
AS I UNDERSTAND IT,
MR. CHEKOV,
THERE ARE THREE
CLASS "M" PLANETS...
YES, SIR.
NOT ONE OF WHICH IS
CAPABLE OF LAUNCHING AN
INTERSTELLAR FLIGHT...
NO, SIR.
YET ONE OF THEM
ACCOMPLISHED IT.
YES, SIR.
THANK YOU, MR. CHEKOV.
CAPTAIN, I'M PICKING UP
HIGH ENERGY GENERATION
ON PLANET 6.
THAT'S THE PRIMITIVE
GLACIATED PLANET.
YES, SIR.
THE SOURCE OF IT?
IT COULD BE NATURAL--
VOLCANIC ACTIVITY, STEAM,
ANY OF A NUMBER OF CAUSES--
BUT IT'S VERY REGULAR.
WHAT DO
YOUR SURFACE
READINGS SHOW?
NO SIGN OF
ORGANIZED CIVILIZATION.
PRIMITIVE HUMANOIDS
PICKED UP AT
IRREGULAR INTERVALS.
WITH REGULAR PULSATIONS
OF GENERATED ENERGY?
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT, SIR.
I CAN'T AFFORD
TO GUESS WRONG.
I'VE GOT TO CHOOSE
THE RIGHT PLANET
TO GET THERE,
FIND THE BRAIN.
8 HOURS
AND 35 MINUTES.
RECOMMENDATIONS,
MR. CHEKOV.
SIGMA DRACONIS 3.
IT'S CLOSEST.
HEAVIEST POPULATION.
BUT A TECHNOLOGICAL
RATING OF ONLY 3.
THEY COULDN'T PUT POSSIBLY HAVE
PUT THAT SHIP WE SAW INTO SPACE.
NONE OF THESE PLANETS
COULD.
I SAY PLANET 4, CAPTAIN.
AT LEAST PLANET 4
IS AHEAD OF 3,
TECHNOLOGICALLY.
BUT ADVANCED ION PROPULSION
IS BEYOND
EVEN OUR CAPABILITIES.
IT'D BE A MIRACLE
IF THEY HAD DEVELOPED IT.
WHAT WOULD THEY WANT
WITH HIS BRAIN?
WITH MR. SPOCK'S BRAIN?
WHAT USE IS IT?
WHY DO THEY WANT IT?
YES. WHY WOULD THEY
WANT IT?
8 HOURS AND 34 MINUTES.
PLANET 6 IS GLACIATED,
YOU SAY?
SEVERAL THOUSAND YEARS,
AT LEAST.
ONLY THE TROPICAL ZONE
IS ICE-FREE.
BUT THE ENERGY.
REGULAR.
IT'S THERE.
IT'S REAL.
YES, SIR.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE,
BUT IT'S THERE.
HAVE THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
STAND BY.
I'M TAKING A LANDING PARTY
DOWN TO PLANET 6.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
A HUNCH, CAPTAIN?
A HUNCH, MR. SULU.
WHAT IF YOU
GUESS WRONG,
CAPTAIN?
IF I GUESS WRONG,
MR. SPOCK IS DEAD.
SPOCK WILL DIE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4351.5.
WE ARE BEAMING DOWN TO A
PRIMITIVE GLACIATED PLANET
IN THE SIGMA DRACONIS
STAR SYSTEM.
TIME LEFT TO US
TO FIND SPOCK'S BRAIN--
8 HOURS AND 29 MINUTES.
SUIT TEMPERATURES TO 72.
LIFE FORM READINGS,
MR. SPOCK--
MR. SCOTT?
SCATTERED.
WIDELY SPACED.
HUMANOID, ALL RIGHT.
ON THE LARGE SIDE.
WATCH OUT. WE KNOW
THEIR DEVELOPMENT
IS PRIMITIVE.
AYE.
READOUT, MR. CHEKOV.
NO STRUCTURES, CAPTAIN.
NO MECHANIZED OBJECTS
THAT I CAN READ.
NO SURFACE CONSUMPTION,
NO GENERATION OF ENERGY.
ATMOSPHERE IS PERFECTLY
ALL RIGHT, OF COURSE.
TEMPERATURE,
A HIGH MAXIMUM OF 40.
LIVABLE.
YOU HAVE A THICK SKIN.
CAPTAIN!
THERE'S SOMEONE,
SOMETHING OUT THERE
IN THE ROCKS.
FIVE OF THEM.
HUMANOID, LARGE.
PHASERS ON STUN.
I WANT THEM CONSCIOUS.
FIRE ONLY ON MY SIGNAL.
FLANK OUT.
CHEKOV.
GRRR!
YAAH!
AAH!
WE MEAN YOU NO HARM.
WE'RE NOT YOUR ENEMIES.
WE'RE YOUR FRIENDS.
WE ONLY WISH
TO TALK TO YOU.
YOU...
ARE NOT THE OTHERS?
NO.
WE COME FROM
A FAR PLACE.
WE ARE MEN.
MEN?
LIKE YOURSELVES.
YOU ARE SMALL...
LIKE THE OTHERS.
WHO ARE THE OTHERS?
THE GIVERS OF PAIN...
AND DELIGHT.
DO THEY LIVE HERE
WITH YOU?
NO. THEY COME.
THEY GIVE PAIN
AND DELIGHT.
DO THEY COME
FROM THE SKY?
THEY ARE HERE.
YOU WILL SEE.
THE OTHERS
WILL COME FOR YOU.
THEY COME...
FOR ALL LIKE US.
DO THEY COME
FOR YOUR WOMEN AS WELL?
WOMEN?
THE FEMALE OF YOUR KIND.
YOUR WORDS SAY NOTHING.
DON'T YOU HAVE A MATE?
MATE?
A COMPANION.
WILL YOU TAKE US WHERE
WE CAN FIND THE OTHERS?
NO ONE WANTS
TO FIND THEM.
WE DO. WE WANT
TAKE US THERE,
AND WE'LL LET YOU GO.
CAPTAIN, 500 METERS
IN THAT DIRECTION,
THERE'S A FOUNDATION
UNDER THE SURFACE.
A HUGE ONE.
REGISTRATIONS
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
BUILDINGS?
YES, SIR. IMMENSELY OLD,
COMPLETELY BURIED.
BUT THEY WERE HERE ONCE.
SOMEWHERE DOWN THERE
IS WHERE THE OTHERS LIVE.
SCOTTY, SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND A WAY DOWN.
NO! NO!
DO NOT GO THERE!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
NO! NO!
LET HIM GO.
WHAT COULD THE OTHERS DO
TO CAUSE SUCH TERROR?
WHAT WAS THAT HE SAID,
"PAIN AND DELIGHT?"
A PECULIAR MIXTURE.
A DEAD AND BURIED CITY
ON A PLANET
IN A GLACIAL AGE.
AND THE MALE HUMANOID
WHO DOESN'T KNOW
THE MEANING OF
THE WORD FEMALE.
CAPTAIN!
OVER HERE, SIR!
THERE'S FOOD IN THERE
AND A WHOLE PILE OF OTHER STUFF.
A STOREHOUSE FOR
OUR MUSCULAR FRIENDS.
I DON'T THINK SO--
SCOTTY.
METAL. FORGED, TEMPERED.
OUR APISH FRIENDS
DIDN'T MAKE THESE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT COULD BE
A WARNING DEVICE
TO KEEP
THOSE CREATURES
AWAY FROM THE FOOD.
OR THE FOOD COULD BE
A LURE SET BY THE OTHERS
TO BRING THEM IN HERE.
IN THAT CASE,
THE BEAM WOULD BE
A SIGNAL.
AND THIS CAVE, A TRAP.
IF IT TRAPS THE CREATURES
FOR THE OTHERS, CAPTAIN,
WON'T IT TRAP US, TOO?
EXACTLY.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
UHURA HERE.
HAVE DR. McCOY
BEAM DOWN IMMEDIATELY.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, YOU
AND THE SECURITY TEAM
WILL REMAIN HERE
AT THE ENTRANCE,
WE'LL BE IN CONSTANT
CONTACT WITH YOU.
AYE, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, BONES.
BRING HIM ALONG.
KEEP HIM CLOSE
TO THE RIGHT.
READY?
[ENGINES START]
CALL CHEKOV AND TELL HIM
TO SEND MY STOMACH DOWN.
IT MIGHT BE A LONG WAIT.
WE MAY AS WELL
BE COMFORTABLE.
PHASERS ON STUN.
CAPTAIN, THAT POWER
WE PICKED UP ABOVE,
WE'RE GETTING CLOSER.
A LOT OF IT?
ENOUGH TO PUSH
THIS PLANET
OUT OF ORBIT.
WHAT SOURCE?
EITHER A NUCLEAR PILE
100 MILES ACROSS OR...
OR WHAT?
ION POWER.
[ENGINES STOP]
WE'RE SLOWING DOWN.
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
I'LL HAVE HER TALKING
IN A MINUTE.
YOU DO NOT BELONG HERE.
YOU ARE NOT MORG.
TAKE ME TO THE ONE IN CHARGE.
I WISH TO SPEAK TO HIM.
HIM? WHAT IS HIM?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH SPOCK'S BRAIN?
WHERE HAVE YOU TAKEN IT?
YOU ARE NOT MORG
OR EYMORG.
I KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT A BRAIN.
YOU'RE LYING!
SEH'S NOT, JIM.
NO CHANGE IN READING.
SHE DOESN'T KNOW.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN PICK UP
ON YOUR COMMUNICATOR.
AYE.
WE DON'T WANT
TO HURT YOU.
WHAT IS THIS PLACE?
THIS PLACE IS HERE.
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM LUMA.
I AM EYMORG.
YOU ARE NOT EYMORG.
YOU ARE NOT MORG.
WHAT ARE YOU?
JIM...
IT'S NO USE.
YOU'LL GET NOTHING
OUT OF THAT ONE.
HERS IS THE MIND
OF A CHILD.
CAPTAIN,
I'VE GOT SOMETHING,
BUT I CAN'T QUITE
GET A FIX ON IT.
[SPOCK]
FASCINATING.
ACTIVITY WITHOUT END,
BUT WITH NO VOLITION.
SPOCK, IS THAT YOU?
CAPTAIN? CAPTAIN KIRK?
YES, SPOCK.
YES.
CAPTAIN,
THERE IS A DEFINITE
PLEASURABLE EXPERIENCE
CONNECTED WITH
THE HEARING OF
YOUR VOICE.
WHERE ARE YOU,
SPOCK?
IS THAT YOU, DR. McCOY,
AND ARE YOU
WITH THE CAPTAIN?
WHERE ELSE
WOULD I BE?
MR. SPOCK,
WHERE ARE YOU?
ENGINEER SCOTT AS WELL.
UNFORTUNATELY,
I DO NOT KNOW WHERE I AM.
WE'LL GET YOU, SPOCK.
IT WON'T BE LONG.
A PRACTICAL IDEA,
CAPTAIN.
IT SEEMS UNLIKELY
THAT I SHALL BE ABLE
TO GET TO YOU.
QUICKLY!
THERE SHE IS.
THAT'S THE ONE.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH SPOCK'S BRAIN?
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5431.6.
IMMEDIATELY AFTER
MAKING CONTACT
WITH SPOCK'S BRAIN,
DR. McCOY,
ENGINEER SCOTT, AND MYSELF
WERE TAKEN PRISONER
INSIDE A HIGHLY
COMPLEX CIVILIZATION
HUNDREDS OF METERS
BELOW THE SURFACE OF
PLANET SIGMA DRACONIS 7.
THE PRIMITIVE CREATURE
WE ENCOUNTERED ABOVE
WARNED US ABOUT THE GIVERS
OF PAIN AND DELIGHT
AND THE FRIGHTENING
CONSEQUENCES OF BEING
CAPTURED BY THEM.
WHAT ARE YOU?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO SPEAK?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH SPOCK'S BRAIN?
WE DO NOT KNOW SPOCK.
THIS IS SPOCK.
YOU SAW HIM ON THE SHIP.
YOU HAVE HIS BRAIN.
IT MUST BE RESTORED
TO HIM IMMEDIATELY.
AH, YES, BRAIN.
YOU SPOKE TO LUMA
ALSO OF BRAIN,
BUT WE DO NOT
UNDERSTAND.
I DO NOT KNOW
ABOUT LUMA,
BUT YOU WERE ON
THE ENTERPRISE.
I SAW YOU.
I DO NOT KNOW
THESE THINGS
YOU SPEAK.
YOU CAME TO MY SHIP!
WE KNOW ONLY
HERE BELOW
AND HERE ABOVE.
THIS IS OUR PLACE.
YOU ARE NOT MORG.
YOU ARE STRANGER.
I SAW YOU ON MY SHIP!
JIM...
SHE MAY NOT REMEMBER...
OR EVEN REALLY KNOW.
DISASSOCIATION
COULD BE COMPLETE.
IT DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE
SHE COULD HAVE
PERFORMED SURGERY
ON SPOCK.
NO, IT DOESN'T.
YOU HURT LUMA.
IT IS NOT PERMITTED AGAIN
TO HURT ANYONE.
SORRY.
WE DON'T WANT
TO HURT ANYONE.
IF YOU WISH TO RETURN
TO YOUR HOME, YOU MAY GO.
NO.
WE'LL STAY HERE
AND LEARN ABOUT YOU
AND TELL YOU OF US.
YES, FOR INSTANCE,
ABOVE IT'S COLD
AND HARSH.
AND BELOW, IT'S WARM.
THE AIR IS FRESH.
AYE. THERE'S NO SUN,
BUT THERE'S LIGHT.
I WISH TO TALK
TO THOSE IN CHARGE.
IN CHARGE?
YES--THE ORGANIZERS,
THE MANAGERS...
THE LEADER
OF YOUR PEOPLE.
I AM LEADER.
THERE IS NO OTHER.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WHO BUILT THE MACHINES?
WHO ARE THE DOCTORS?
WHO OPERATES?
WHO CONTROLS
THIS COMPLEX?
CONTROL?
CONTROLLER?
YES, THE CONTROLLER.
THE CONTROLLER.
WHO...WHO CONTROLS?
I WOULD LIKE TO MEET--
TO SEE HIM.
NO. IT IS NOT PERMITTED.
NEVER!
CONTROLLER IS ALONE.
APART.
WE SERVE CONTROLLER.
NO OTHER
IS PERMITTED NEAR.
WE INTEND NO HARM.
YOU HAVE COME
TO DESTROY US.
NO, NO, NO.
I PROMISE YOU.
WE JUST WANT TO TALK
TO SOMEBODY ABOUT
SPOCK'S BRAIN, THAT'S ALL.
BRAIN AND BRAIN!
WHAT IS BRAIN?
IT IS CONTROLLER,
IS IT NOT?
YES, YES,
IN A WAY IT IS.
THE HUMAN BRAIN CONTROLS
THE INDIVIDUAL'S FUNCTIONS.
BONES...
SCOTTY...
SPOCK'S BRAIN
CONTROLS...
IT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
GREAT...LEADER.
GREAT LEADER!
WE COME FROM A FAR PLACE
TO LEARN FROM
YOUR CONTROLLER.
YOU LIE! YOU KNOW ME.
YOU HAVE SAID THAT.
YOU CAME TO TAKE BACK
THE CONTROLLER.
HE IS OUR FRIEND.
YOU MUST TAKE US TO HIM.
WE BEG YOU.
SOON IT WILL BE
TOO LATE.
DO NOT TAKE THEM,
KARA.
DO NOT TAKE THEM
TO THE CONTROLLER!
THEY WILL BE PREVENTED.
YOU MUST TAKE US--
I MUST LEARN WHAT TO DO.
COME WITH ME.
KEEP THEM HERE.
YES, MISTRESS.
SHIP'S LOG.
LIEUTENANT SULU RECORDING.
I AM HOLDING THE ENTERPRISE
IN ORBIT
ABOUT
PLANET SIGMA DRACONIS 7.
CAPTAIN KIRK'S HUNCH
THAT SPOCK'S BRAIN
IS ON THIS PLANET
APPEARS TO BE CORRECT.
ENSIGN CHEKOV
REMAINS ON THE SURFACE
TO ACT AS LIAISON
BETWEEN THE CAPTAIN
AND THE ENTERPRISE.
I NEVER FELT ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
EVERY NERVE IN MY BODY
WAS ON FIRE.
I NEVER BELIEVED
THE HUMAN ORGANISM
COULD TAKE SUCH PAIN.
AYE, THESE ARE
ON TO STAY FOR
A WHILE, TOO.
MUST BE
A MAGNETIC LOCK
OF SOME KIND.
NO WONDER THE MORGS
ARE SO OBEDIENT...
OR TERRIFIED.
HOW IS THIS PLACE
KEPT FUNCTIONING
BY THE PRIMITIVE MINDS
WE'VE MET?
THOSE WOMEN COULD
NEVER HAVE SET UP
ANYTHING AS
COMPLEX AS THIS.
WHY, THAT TAKES
ENGINEERING GENIUS.
BUT THERE'S NO SIGN
OF ENGINEERING GENIUS
IN ANY OF THOSE WOMEN.
THEY WERE SMART ENOUGH
TO INVENT THESE
TRAINING DEVICES.
WHAT A WAY TO MAINTAIN
CONTROL OVER A MAN.
"PAIN AND DELIGHT,"
HE SAID UP ABOVE.
I'M SURE YOU NOTICED
THE DELIGHT ASPECT
OF THIS PLACE.
YES, I CERTAINLY DID NOTICE
THOSE DELIGHTFUL ASPECTS.
BUT THAT, TOO,
WAS STRICTLY UNDER COMMAND
OF THE WOMEN.
HOW DOES
SPOCK'S BRAIN
FIT INTO THIS?
WITH A COMMUNICATOR,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO FIND OUT.
THIS FELLOW
IS KEEPING US
FROM OUR PROPERTY.
ISN'T THERE A WAY
TO CORRECT THAT SITUATION?
I CERTAINLY THINK
THAT SCIENCE MIGHT
PROVIDE AN ANSWER.
IT DOES, CAPTAIN.
AGREED, DOCTOR.
SCIENCE WILL TRIUMPH.
COME ON, SCOTTY.
BONES, GIVE THEM SOMETHING
THAT WILL KEEP THEM OUT
FOR A WHILE.
SPOCK.
COME ON, SPOCK.
SPOCK, YOU WERE ON
THIS FREQUENCY, SPOCK.
YES, CAPTAIN,
I AM STILL HERE.
HAVE YOU RETURNED
TO THE ENTERPRISE?
NO.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO LOCATE YOU,
IF YOU GAVE US SOME IDEA OF
WHAT THEY WERE USING YOU FOR.
IS IT MEDICAL?
I AM NOT CERTAIN.
I SEEM TO HAVE A BODY
WHICH STRETCHES
INTO INFINITY.
BODY?
WHY, YOU HAVE NONE.
THEN WHAT AM I?
YOU ARE
A DISEMBODIED BRAIN.
FASCINATING.
IT COULD EXPLAIN MUCH,
DOCTOR.
MY MEDULLA OBLONGATA
IS HARD AT WORK
APPARENTLY BREATHING,
APPARENTLY
PUMPING BLOOD,
APPARENTLY MAINTAINING
A NORMAL PHYSIOLOGIC
TEMPERATURE.
SPOCK, WE DON'T
HAVE TIME FOR THAT.
WHY ARE YOU ENDANGERING
YOUR LIVES BY COMING HERE?
WE CAME TO PUT YOU BACK.
WHERE ARE YOU?
BACK WHERE?
BACK INTO YOUR BODY.
WE BROUGHT IT
ALONG WITH US.
THOUGHTFUL, CAPTAIN,
BUT PROBABLY IMPRACTICAL.
WHILE I MIGHT
TRUST THE DOCTOR
TO REMOVE A SPLINTER
OR LANCE A BOIL,
I DO NOT BELIEVE
HE HAS THE KNOWLEDGE
TO RESTORE A BRAIN.
THANK YOU.
NO DENIGRATION
INTENDED, DR. McCOY.
THAT SKILL DOES NOT YET
EXIST IN THE GALAXY.
THE SKILL TO REMOVE IT
EXISTS RIGHT WHERE WE ARE.
RESTORING IT MUST
ALSO BE POSSIBLE.
THAT'S WHY WE'VE GOT
TO GET TO YOU AS QUICKLY
AS WE CAN.
CAPTAIN, I APPRECIATE
THE RISKS YOU'RE TAKING
ON MY BEHALF,
BUT I MUST INSIST
THAT THEY ARE WORTHWHILE
ONLY IF THERE'S
A REASONABLE CHANCE
FOR SUCCESS.
LET ME ASK YOU,
HOW MUCH TIME
HAS ELAPSED SINCE--
18 HOURS AND 12 MINUTES.
DR. McCOY MUST'VE TOLD YOU
THAT 24 HOURS
IS THE MAXIMUM
MY BODY CAN--
I TOLD HIM.
THAT LEAVES US
EXACTLY 5 HOURS
AND 48 MINUTES, SPOCK.
IT DOES SEEM
ALL TOO BRIEF A TIME
TO DEVELOP SUCH SKILLS,
DOES IT NOT?
YES.
VERY BRIEF.
THAT'S WHY WE MUST
GET TO YOU IMMEDIATELY.
BEAM US A SIGNAL
SO WE CAN HOME IN ON.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
[BEEP]
GOT IT.
BONES.
OH, SPOCK,
ONE QUESTION.
YES, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE GOT PAIN-GIVING
DEVICES ATTACHED TO US.
CAN YOU TELL US HOW
TO GET THEM OFF?
I SHALL GIVE IT
TOP-PRIORITY.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE
AN ANSWER FOR YOU.
IT SEEMS YOUR PAIN BANDS
ARE MANUALLY CONTROLLED.
THE RED BUTTON
ON A BRACELET
RELEASES THEM.
I KNOW THAT DOES NOT
MAKE MUCH SENSE.
OH, YES, IT DOES,
SPOCK.
KEEP CONCENTRATING,
MUST BE IN THERE,
CAPTAIN.
JIM...
SPOCK...
NO PAIN.
NO.
GO AWAY.
WE WILL DIE!
YOU MUST NOT TAKE
THE CONTROLLER AWAY.
WE WILL ALL DIE!
THE CONTROLLER IS
YOUNG AND POWERFUL.
PERFECT!
HOW VERY FLATTERING.
YOU WILL GIVE LIFE
TO MY PEOPLE
FOR 10,000 YEARS TO COME.
YOU'LL FIND
ANOTHER CONTROLLER.
THE OLD ONE
IS FINISHED!
THERE IS
NO OTHER
THAN THIS
AND WILL NOT
BE ANOTHER FOR
10,000 YEARS.
SPOCK, YOU'RE IN
A BLACK BOX TIED IN
WITH LIGHT RAYS
INTO A COMPLEX
CONTROL PANEL.
FASCINATING.
YOU SAY
YOU'RE BREATHING,
PUMPING BLOOD,
MAINTAINING
TEMPERATURE?
IS IT POSSIBLE
THAT YOU'RE
RECIRCULATING AIR,
RUNNING
HEATING PLANTS,
PURIFYING WATER?
INDEED, CAPTAIN.
THAT IS UNQUESTIONABLY
PART OF WHAT I AM DOING.
HE MUST STAY!
HE WILL NOT STAY.
NOW, YOU TOOK HIS BRAIN.
YOU WILL PUT IT BACK.
HOW DID YOU DO IT?
I DO NOT KNOW.
SHE COULDN'T, JIM.
HER MIND IS FUNCTIONING
ON A VERY SIMPLE LEVEL.
MENTAL FACULTIES
DOWN HERE SEEM TO BE
ALMOST ATROPHIED
BECAUSE OF NONUSE.
SHE WAS ON
THE ENTERPRISE.
SHE MUST HAVE DONE IT.
HOW DID YOU DO IT?
IT WAS
THE OLD KNOWLEDGE.
HOW DO YOU GET IT?
I PUT UPON MY HEAD
THE TEACHER.
WHAT IS THE TEACHER?
THE GREAT TEACHER OF
ALL THE ANCIENT KNOWLEDGE.
IF I MAY EXPLAIN, CAPTAIN,
SHE REFERS TO
THE TAPE STOREHOUSE
OF KNOWLEDGE
OF THE BUILDERS
OF THIS PLACE.
I SCAN IT.
A MOST IMPRESSIVE STORE.
HOW DOES IT WORK?
SHOW US.
I CANNOT.
YOU MUST TELL US.
ONLY BY COMMAND
OF THE ANCIENTS
MAY I UNDERSTAND.
HOW DOES IT WORK?
SHOW US!
WE'LL PROTECT YOU.
YOU WON'T COME
TO ANY HARM.
IT IS A DEVICE
WITH FEEDING CIRCUITS.
THEY LEAD INTO THE MIND
OF THE PRIESTESS LEADER.
ITS USE IS STRICTLY
PREDETERMINED
BY THE BUILDERS.
NO! KNOWLEDGE IS FORBIDDEN!
I MUST NOT KNOW THE SECRET!
I'LL BE PUNISHED!
GENTLEMEN...
THE CONTROLLER'S EXPLANATION
OF THE FUNCTIONING
OF THE TEACHER
IS ESSENTIALLY CORRECT.
HOWEVER, HE IS GIVING
NO CREDIT TO ME.
I PROVIDE THE MEANS
WHEREBY THE KNOWLEDGE
IS USED.
WITHOUT ME, CAPTAIN--
WITHOUT YOU
THERE COULD BE
NO DELICATE MIRACLE
THAT KEPT SPOCK'S
BRAIN ALIVE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
THAT WAS VERY GRACIOUS.
YES. FROM THE VERY FIRST,
I APPRECIATED YOUR ABILITY.
GOOD, CAPTAIN KIRK.
THEN YOU WILL ALSO APPRECIATE
THAT WITHOUT THE TEACHER,
I WOULD NOT HAVE
THE KNOWLEDGE TO USE
THAT WHICH YOU HAVE
THOUGHTFULLY PROVIDED.
THAT PHASER
IS SET TO KILL.
SO IT IS.
THAT IS THE KNOWLEDGE
YOU HAVE BROUGHT ME.
DO NOT MOVE.
IF YOUR WEAPON KILLS,
IT WILL KILL YOU.
WE'RE NOT THE FIRST TO
BRING YOU THE KNOWLEDGE
OF KILLING.
IF YOU CONTINUE,
YOU'LL KILL SPOCK.
THE CONTROLLER DIE?
THE CONTROLLER WILL
LIVE FOR 10,000 YEARS,
AND WE SHALL GIVE HIM
ALL OUR DEVOTION.
BUT SPOCK WILL BE DEAD.
HIS BODY'S DYING
THIS MINUTE.
WHY DO YOU
NOT UNDERSTAND THAT
THE NEED OF MY PEOPLE
FOR THEIR CONTROLLER
IS GREATER
THAN YOUR NEED
FOR YOUR FRIEND?
NO ONE MAY KILL A MAN!
NOT FOR ANY PURPOSE.
IT CANNOT BE CONDONED.
DO NOT!
I DO NOT KNOW KILLING.
I DO NOT WISH TO KILL.
AH...
THE COMMANDMENT
MUST BE FULFILLED.
YOU MUST HELP US.
WHEN YOU CAME
TO THE SHIP,
YOU HAD THE KNOWLEDGE.
YET, WHEN WE CAME HERE,
YOU DIDN'T.
CORRECT.
HOW LONG DOES
THE KNOWLEDGE LAST?
THREE OF YOUR HOURS.
THAT WOULD BE
JUST ENOUGH TIME.
IF YOU HAD
THE KNOWLEDGE,
COULD YOU RESTORE
WHAT YOU'VE TAKEN?
I WOULD NOT.
YOU MUST HELP US.
YOU MUST RESTORE
WITH THAT KNOWLEDGE
WHAT YOU HAVE TAKEN.
NO!
YOU MUST PUT BACK
WHAT YOU HAVE TAKEN.
I WILL NOT BETRAY
MY PEOPLE.
THE CONTROLLER WILL STAY.
JIM, IT WORKED FOR HER.
IT MIGHT WORK FOR ME.
SHE IS AN ALIEN.
THE CONFIGURATIONS
OF HER BRAIN ARE DIFFERENT.
IT COULD CAUSE IRREPARABLE
DAMAGE TO YOUR HUMAN BRAIN,
DOCTOR.
I'M A SURGEON ALREADY.
IF I COULD LEARN
THESE TECHNIQUES,
I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO RETAIN THEM.
CAPTAIN, YOU MIGHT LOSE
THE DOCTOR THAT WAY.
HE MIGHT,
BUT WE'RE SURE TO LOSE
YOU IF I DON'T TRY.
I CANNOT ALLOW YOU
TO JEOPARDIZE YOUR LIFE
FOR ME.
SPOCK,
DIDN'T YOU HEAR?
I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO RETAIN AND BRING
THESE TECHNIQUES
TO THE WORLD.
JIM, ISN'T IT WORTH
THAT RISK?
WOULDN'T YOU INSIST
UPON TAKING SUCH
A RISK YOURSELF?
GO AHEAD, DOCTOR.
PUT THE TEACHER ON.
NO!
OF COURSE.
A CHILD COULD DO IT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STARDATE 5432.3.
DR. McCOY IS PROCEEDING
TO RESTORE SPOCK'S BRAIN.
OUR PROBLEM--
WE DO NOT KNOW HOW LONG
HIS INCREASED
SURGICAL KNOWLEDGE
WILL STAY WITH HIM.
ANY ADDITIONAL ATTEMPT
TO USE THE TEACHING DEVICE
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
IT WOULD KILL
MY MEDICAL OFFICER.
I HAVEN'T SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
HE'S OPERATING
AT WARP SPEED.
I'D LIKE A TRY
AT THAT TEACHER MYSELF.
YOU WILL HAVE HIM
BACK,
AND WE WILL
BE DESTROYED.
NO. YOU WON'T
YOU'LL BE WITHOUT
YOUR CONTROLLER
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
BUT YOU'LL BE
MUCH BETTER OFF,
I THINK.
WE WILL DIE.
NO. YOU WILL LIVE
AND DEVELOP AS YOU
SHOULD HAVE.
ALL THIS SHOULDN'T
HAVE BEEN DONE FOR YOU.
NOW THE WOMEN HERE BELOW
AND THE MEN HERE ABOVE
WILL CONTROL TOGETHER.
THEY WILL NOT HELP US
WITHOUT THE PAIN.
THERE ARE OTHER WAYS.
YOU'LL DISCOVER THEM.
YOU MUST MOVE TO THE SURFACE,
YOU UNDERSTAND.
WE WILL DIE ABOVE
IN THE COLD.
NO, YOU WON'T.
YOU'LL LEARN TO BUILD HOUSES,
TO KEEP WARM,
TO WORK.
WE'LL HELP YOU
FOR A WHILE.
HUMANS HAVE SURVIVED
UNDER WORSE CONDITIONS.
IT'S A MATTER OF EVOLUTION.
YOU'LL DO FINE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
WHAT IS IT?
HE'S FORGETTING.
I CAN'T--I--
BONES.
ALL THE GANGLIA--
THE NERVES.
THERE ARE A MILLION
OF THEM.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
BONES, YOU CAN'T STOP NOW.
I'M TRYING TO THREAD A NEEDLE
WITH A SLEDGEHAMMER.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
I DON'T REMEMBER.
BONES.
NO ONE CAN RESTORE A BRAIN.
YOU COULD.
A WHILE AGO,
IT WAS CHILD'S PLAY.
CAPTAIN'S LOG SUPPLEMENTAL.
OUR RACE AGAINST TIME
TO SAVE SPOCK'S LIFE
MAY HAVE BEEN FUTILE.
DR. McCOY HAS LOST
THE SURGICAL KNOWLEDGE
HE OBTAINED
FROM THE TEACHER.
HE HAS BEEN DRAWING
ON HIS OWN SKILLS
AND SURGICAL TECHNIQUES
IN AN ATTEMPT
TO CONTINUE THE OPERATION,
BUT HE IS FALTERING
AND UNCERTAIN.
IN A DESPERATE HOPE
THAT HE CAN DRAW ON SPOCK'S
BRAIN FOR ASSISTANCE,
I INSTRUCTED DR. McCOY
TO GIVE PRIORITY
TO CONNECTING
SPOCK'S VOCAL CHORDS.
WELL?
HE'S DYING,
AND I CAN'T STOP IT.
YES...
DR. McCOY...
SPOCK.
IF YOU WILL FINISH
RECONNECTING
MY SPEECH CENTER,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO HELP.
SPEECH CENTER.
YES. THAT'S CORRECT.
ONE THING AT A TIME.
AHH...
MMM...
THAT'S BETTER.
NOW, DOCTOR,
TRY THE SONIC SEPARATOR.
SONIC SEPARATOR.
YES,
I BELIEVE I ALREADY HAVE
SOME SENSATION OF FEELING.
PLEASE STIMULATE
THE NERVE ENDINGS
AND OBSERVE
THE PHYSICAL REACTIONS,
ONE BY ONE.
IN EACH CASE,
I SHALL TELL YOU WHEN
THE PROBE IS CORRECT.
YOU WILL THEN SEAL USING
THE TRI-LASER CONNECTOR.
TRI-LASER CONNECTOR.
READY?
READY.
RIGHT FOREFINGER.
CORRECT.
RIGHT...
WRIST.
CORRECT.
RIGHT ELBOW.
VERY GOOD, DOCTOR.
I'LL NEVER LIVE THIS DOWN--
THIS VULCAN IS TELLING ME
HOW TO OPERATE.
CLOSED.
WELL?
HOW DO I KNOW?
I COULD HAVE MADE
A THOUSAND MISTAKES.
SEALING NERVE ENDINGS,
JOINING GANGLIA.
THE FLUID BALANCE
IS CORRECT, BUT...
I DON'T KNOW.
CONGRATULATIONS, DOCTOR,
AND THANK YOU.
HOW DO YOU FEEL, SPOCK?
ON THE WHOLE, CAPTAIN,
I BELIEVE I'M QUITE FIT.
IT'S FASCINATING.
A REMARKABLE EXAMPLE
OF A RETROGRADE
CIVILIZATION.
AT THE PEAK,
ADVANCED BEYOND ANY
OF OUR CAPABILITIES
AND NOW OPERATING
AT THIS PRIMITIVE LEVEL
WHICH YOU SAW.
AND IT ALL BEGAN
THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO
WHEN A GLACIAL AGE
REOCCURRED. YOU SEE,
THIS UNDERGROUND
COMPLEX WAS DEVELOPED
FOR THE WOMEN.
THE MEN REMAINED ABOVE.
AND A MALE-FEMALE SCHISM
TOOK PLACE.
A FASCINATING CULTURAL
DEVELOPMENT OF--
I KNEW IT WAS WRONG.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE IT.
WHAT'S THAT?
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER
RECONNECTED HIS MOUTH.
WELL, WE TOOK THE RISK,
DOCTOR.
AS I WAS SAYING,
A FASCINATING CULTURAL
DEVELOPMENT OF THE KIND
WHICH HASN'T BEEN SEEN
IN AGES.
THE LAST SUCH OCCURRENCE
TOOK PLACE ON OLD EARTH
WHEN THE ROMANS...