ENTERPRISE MEDICAL LOG,
STARDATE 5027.3.
DR. LEONARD McCOY
RECORDING.
I'M CONCERNED ABOUT
CAPTAIN KIRK.
HE SHOWS INDICATIONS
OF INCREASING TENSION
AND EMOTIONAL STRESS.
I HAVE COMPLETED
THE ASSIGNMENT, CAPTAIN.
"A THEORETICAL INCURSION
INTO--"
YES, MR. CHEKOV.
I CAN READ.
AND AS USUAL, YOUR
THEORETICAL EVALUATIONS
DO NOT TALLY WITH MINE.
RETURN TO YOUR DUTY,
AND I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN YOUR WORK
IS SATISFACTORY.
MR. SPOCK.
FULL SENSOR SCAN
OF THE REGION, PLEASE.
I DID GAVE A FULL REPORT
ON IT JUST--
YES, MR. SPOCK.
THAT WAS THE PAST.
I'M CONCERNED
WITH THE PRESENT.
OR IS IT BECOMING
TOO MUCH FOR THIS CREW
TO PRESENT ME
CURRENT INFORMATION?
NO, SIR. COMPLIANCE
PRESENTS NO PROBLEM.
THEN, MR. SPOCK, COMPLY.
SENSOR SCAN
TO ONE-HALF PARSEC.
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
VERY WELL.
I CAN FIND NO REASON
FOR THE CAPTAIN'S BEHAVIOR,
EXCEPT POSSIBLY THAT WE'VE
BEEN ON PATROL TOO LONG
WITHOUT RELIEF
AND DIVERSION.
HE HAS RESISTED
ALL OF MY ATTEMPTS
TO RUN A PSYCHOLOGICAL
PROFILE ON HIM.
MAINTAINING COURSE
AND SPEED, SIR.
CHANGE COURSE.
COME ABOUT
TO 185, MARK 3.
BUT, SIR,
THAT'LL LEAD US
DIRECTLY INTO
THE ROMULAN NEUTRAL ZONE.
YES, VERY PERCEPTIVE,
MR. SULU.
I KNOW WHERE
THE COURSE CHANGE
TAKES US.
EXECUTE.
AYE, SIR.
INCREASING SENSOR SCAN
TO ONE PARSEC.
ALL SCANNERS REPORT CLEAR.
NOTHING IN OUR
IMMEDIATE VICINITY.
BETTER AND BETTER,
MR. SPOCK.
CAPTAIN, LEAVING
NEUTRAL ZONE.
NOW ENTERING
ROMULAN SPACE.
VERY WELL, MR. SULU.
LIEUTENANT, WHEN DID
THE ORDER COME THROUGH?
ORDER?
FROM STARFLEET.
THE ORDER TO ENTER
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
THERE'S BEEN NO ORDER
I KNOW OF, MR. SCOTT.
SURELY THE CAPTAIN
COULDN'T BE DOING THIS
ON HIS OWN AUTHORITY.
IF YOU TWO
HAVE COMPLAINTS,
YOU CAN BRING THEM
OUT INTO THE OPEN.
THAT'S A KLINGON SHIP!
BIT IT COULDN'T BE,
NOT IN THIS AREA.
INTELLIGENCE REPORTS
ROMULANS NOW USING
KLINGON DESIGN.
SOUND RED ALERT.
MAN BATTLE STATIONS.
STAND BY
MAIN PHASERS.
BATTLE STATIONS.
ALL HANDS, BATTLE STATIONS.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
SECOND SHIP HAS APPEARED.
CORRECTION...
THERE ARE NOW 3.
WE ARE SURROUNDED.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CODE A MESSAGE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
ADVISE THEM
OF OUR SITUATION.
INCLUDE ALL LOG ENTRIES
TO THIS POINT.
MR. SPOCK, YOUR SENSORS
READ CLEAR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I HAVE A THEORY,
CAPTAIN, THAT--
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I'M RECEIVING
CLASS 2 SIGNAL
FROM THE ROMULAN
VESSEL.
PUT IT ON THE MAIN
VIEWING SCREEN, LIEUTENANT,
AND COMPLETE THAT MESSAGE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
AYE, SIR.
YOU HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE,
CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK
LAST KNOWN
TO BE IN COMMAND.
YOUR INFORMATION
IS CORRECT.
THIS IS
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I AM SUBCOMMANDER TAL
OF THE ROMULAN FLEET.
YOUR SHIP IS
SURROUNDED, CAPTAIN.
YOU WILL SURRENDER
IMMEDIATELY
OR WE WILL DESTROY YOU.
LIEUTENANT.
THEY WANT SOMETHING,
OR THEY WOULD HAVE
DESTROYED US BY NOW.
TRUE, CAPTAIN.
THAT WOULD BE
STANDARD ROMULAN PROCEDURE.
IT'S MY SHIP THEY WANT,
AND VERY BADLY.
IT WOULD BE
A GREAT PRIZE.
LIEUTENANT.
SAVE YOUR THREATS.
IF YOU
BOARD THIS SHIP,
I'LL BLOW IT UP.
YOU'LL GAIN NOTHING.
WHO IS THAT BESIDE YOU?
MY FIRST OFFICER,
COMMANDER SPOCK.
A VULCAN.
[BEEP BEEP]
YES, COMMANDER?
YES, COMMANDER.
NO ONE SHOULD DECIDE QUICKLY
TO DIE, CAPTAIN.
WE GIVE YOU
ONE OF YOUR HOURS.
IF YOU DO NOT
SURRENDER YOUR SHIP
AT THE END OF THAT TIME,
YOUR DESTRUCTION
IS CERTAIN.
WE WILL BE OPEN
TO COMMUNICATION
SHOULD YOU WISH IT.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT
STARFLEET COMMAND
HAS BEEN ADVISED
OF THE SITUATION?
A SUBSPACE MESSAGE
WILL TAKE 3 WEEKS
TO REACH STARFLEET.
THE DECISION IS YOURS,
CAPTAIN.
ONE HOUR.
THE DESIGN OF THE SHIP
IS THE SAME.
MR. SPOCK, YOU SAID
YOU HAD A THEORY
ON WHY YOUR SENSORS
DIDN'T PICK UP
THE NEW SHIPS
UNTIL THEY WERE
UPON US?
I BELIEVE THE ROMULANS
HAVE DEVELOPED
A CLOAKING DEVICE
WHICH RENDERS OUR
TRACKING SENSORS
USELESS.
IF SO, ROMULANS COULD ATTACK
IN FEDERATION TERRITORY
BEFORE WE KNEW
THEY WERE THERE...
BEFORE A VESSEL
OR A PLANET
COULD EVEN BEGIN TO
GET THEIR DEFENSES UP.
THEY CAUGHT US
RIGHT ENOUGH.
THAT'S A BRILLIANT
OBSERVATION, MR. SCOTT.
DO YOU HAVE
ANY HELPFUL OPINIONS?
WELL, WE'VE NOT GOT
MANY CHOICES.
WE HAVE 3--
WE CAN FIGHT
AND BE DESTROYED,
OR WE CAN DESTROY
THE ENTERPRISE OURSELVES
AND KEEP HER FROM THE ROMULANS,
OR WE CAN...
SURRENDER.
OPINIONS, GENTLEMEN.
IF THE ENTERPRISE
IS TAKEN BY ROMULANS,
THEY'LL KNOW EVERYTHING
THERE IS TO KNOW
ABOUT A STARSHIP.
IF WE HAD NOT CROSSED
THE NEUTRAL ZONE,
ON YOUR ORDER,
YOU WOULD NOT NOW
NEED OUR OPINIONS
TO SUPPORT A DECISION
WHICH SHOULD NEVER
HAVE HAD TO BE MADE.
JIM, YOU ORDERED US?
YOU HAD NO AUTHORITY.
DISMISSED, DOCTOR.
JIM--
I SAID DISMISSED.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
THE ROMULAN VESSEL
IS SIGNALING AGAIN, SIR.
PUT THEM ON THE SCREEN.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MY COMMANDER WISHES
TO SPEAK WITH YOU,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
PUT HIM ON.
THE COMMANDER WISHES
TO SEE YOU
AND YOUR FIRST OFFICER
ABOARD THIS VESSEL.
IT IS FELT THIS MATTER
REQUIRES DISCUSSION.
WHY SHOULD WE WALK
RIGHT INTO YOUR HANDS?
TWO OF MY OFFICERS WILL
BEAM ABOARD YOUR VESSEL
AS EXCHANGE HOSTAGES
WHILE YOU ARE HERE.
WHAT GUARANTEE
DO WE HAVE
THAT THEY'LL BEAM ABOARD
OUR SHIP ONCE WE'RE ON YOURS?
GRANTED WE DO NOT EASILY
TRUST EACH OTHER, CAPTAIN,
BUT YOU ARE THE ONES WHO
VIOLATED OUR TERRITORY.
SHOULD IT NOT BE WE
WHO DISTRUST YOUR MOTIVES?
HOWEVER, WE AGREE
TO SIMULTANEOUS EXCHANGE.
GIVE US YOUR
TRANSPORTER COORDINATES.
WE'RE BEAMING ABOARD.
ONE FINAL ORDER,
ENGINEER SCOTT--
IF WE DO NOT RETURN,
THE ENTERPRISE
MUST NOT BE TAKEN.
IF THE ROMULANS
ATTEMPT IT,
YOU'RE TO FIGHT,
AND IF NECESSARY,
DESTROY YOURSELVES.
IS THAT CLEAR?
PERFECTLY CLEAR.
ENERGIZE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
COMMANDER...
I'M HONORED.
I DON'T THINK SO...
BUT WE HAVE AN IMPORTANT
MATTER TO DISCUSS.
AND YOUR SUPERFICIAL
COURTESIES
ARE AN OVERTURE
TO THAT DISCUSSION.
YOU ARE THE FIRST OFFICER?
SPOCK.
I SPEAK FIRST
WITH THE CAPTAIN.
YOU MAY WAIT OUTSIDE.
THE MATTER OF TRESPASS
INTO ROMULAN SPACE
IS ONE OF GALACTIC IMPORT,
A VIOLATION OF TREATIES.
NOW I ASK YOU SIMPLY,
WHAT IS
YOUR MISSION HERE?
INSTRUMENT FAILURE
CAUSED NAVIGATIONAL ERROR.
WE WERE ACROSS
THE NEUTRAL ZONE
BEFORE WE REALIZED IT,
THEN WE WERE SURROUNDED
BY YOUR SHIPS
BEFORE WE COULD
GET BACK.
A STARSHIP,
ONE OF THE STARFLEET'S
FINEST VESSELS?
YOU'RE SAYING
INSTRUMENT FAILURE
AS RADICAL AS YOU SUGGEST
WENT UNNOTICED
UNTIL YOU WERE
WELL PAST THE NEUTRAL ZONE?
ACCIDENTS CAN HAPPEN.
CUT OFF, BACKUP
SYSTEMS CAN MALFUNCTION.
WE WERE DUE FOR AN OVERHAUL
TWO MONTHS AGO.
I SEE.
BUT YOU WERE ABLE TO NAVIGATE
WITH THIS MALFUNCTION?
THE ERROR WAS CORRECTED.
BUT I DOUBT IT IT WILL
CLEAR YOU OF ESPIONAGE.
WE WERE NOT SPYING,
COMMANDER.
YOUR LANGUAGE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN MOST DIFFICULT
FOR ME, CAPTAIN.
PERHAPS YOU HAVE
ANOTHER WORD FOR IT.
YOU ARE GROSSLY MISTAKEN
IF YOU THINK THAT
WE WERE THERE TO--
CAPTAIN, IF A ROMULAN VESSEL
VENTURED FAR INTO
FEDERATION TERRITORY
WITHOUT GOOD EXPLANATION,
WHAT WOULD A STAR BASE
COMMANDER DO?
YOU SEE...
IT WORKS BOTH WAYS.
I HARDLY BELIEVE
YOU ARE THE INJURED PARTY.
SPOCK, COME IN.
THE CAPTAIN HAS MADE
HIS STATEMENT.
I UNDERSTAND.
I MUST ADMIT SOME SURPRISE
ON SEEING YOU, SPOCK.
WE WERE NOT AWARE
OF VULCANS ABOARD
THE ENTERPRISE.
STARFLEET
IS NOT IN THE HABIT
OF INFORMING ROMULANS
OF ITS SHIPS' PERSONNEL.
QUITE SO, YET THERE ARE
CERTAIN SHIPS...
CERTAIN OFFICERS...
THAT ARE KNOWN TO US.
YOUR SITUATION APPEARS
MOST INTERESTING.
WHAT EARNS SPOCK
YOUR SPECIAL INTEREST?
HE IS A VULCAN.
OUR FOREBEARS
HAD THE SAME ROOTS
AND ORIGINS.
SOMETHING YOU WOULDN'T
UNDERSTAND, CAPTAIN.
WE CAN APPRECIATE
THE VULCANS,
OUR DISTANT BROTHERS.
I HAVE HEARD
OF VULCAN INTEGRITY
AND PERSONAL HONOR.
THERE'S
A WELL-KNOWN SAYING--
OR IS IT A MYTH--
THAT VULCANS
ARE INCAPABLE OF LYING?
IT IS NO MYTH.
THEN TELL ME
TRUTHFULLY NOW,
BY YOUR HONOR
AS A VULCAN,
WHAT WAS YOUR MISSION?
I RESERVE THE PRIVILEGE
OF SPEAKING
ONLY WHEN IT WILL NOT
VIOLATE MY HONOR
AS A VULCAN.
IT IS UNWORTHY
OF A VULCAN
TO RESORT TO SUBTERFUGE.
YOU'RE BEING CLEVER,
COMMANDER.
THAT IS UNWORTHY
OF A ROMULAN.
IT IS NOT A LIE
TO KEEP THE TRUTH
TO ONESELF.
OH, THEN THERE IS
A TRUTH HERE
THAT REMAINS UNSPOKEN.
YOU'VE BEEN TOLD EVERYTHING.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE TO SAY.
THERE IS MR. SPOCK'S
UNSPOKEN TRUTH.
YOU KNEW OF
THE CLOAKING DEVICE
THAT WE HAVE DEVELOPED.
YOU DELIBERATELY
VIOLATED ROMULAN SPACE
WITH A BLATANT SPY MISSION,
BY ORDER OF THE FEDERATION--
WE'VE BEEN ALL THROUGH THAT,
COMMANDER.
WE HAVE NOT EVEN BEGUN!
THERE'S NO FORCE
THAT I CAN USE
ON A VULCAN
THAT WILL MAKE HIM SPEAK.
THAT IS A FACT.
BUT THERE ARE
ROMULAN METHODS
COMPLETELY EFFECTIVE
AGAINST HUMANS
AND HUMAN WEAKNESSES.
YOU WOULD NOT RESORT
TO THEM, COMMANDER.
THEY WOULD PROVE
INEFFECTIVE AGAINST
THE CAPTAIN.
THEN THEY WILL
LEAVE HIM DEAD...
OR WHAT MIGHT BE WORSE
THAN DEAD,
BUT I WILL KNOW
YOUR UNSPOKEN TRUTHS.
LET HER RANT.
THERE'S NOTHING TO SAY.
I CANNOT ALLOW THE CAPTAIN
TO BE FURTHER DESTROYED.
THE STRAIN OF COMMAND
HAS WORN HEAVILY UPON HIM.
HE HAS NOT BEEN HIMSELF
FOR SEVERAL WEEKS.
THAT'S A LIE!
AS YOU CAN SEE, CAPTAIN KIRK
IS A HIGHLY SENSITIVE
AND EMOTIONAL PERSON.
I BELIEVE HE HAS
LOST THE CAPACITY
FOR RATIONAL DECISION.
SHUT UP, SPOCK!
I AM BETRAYING NO SECRETS.
THE COMMANDER'S SUSPICION
THAT STARFLEET ORDERED
THE ENTERPRISE
INTO THE NEUTRAL ZONE
IS UNACCEPTABLE.
OUR RAPID CAPTURE
DEMONSTRATES ITS FOOLHARDINESS.
YOU'RE A FILTHY LIAR!
I AM SPEAKING THE TRUTH,
FOR THE BENEFIT
OF THE ENTERPRISE
AND THE FEDERATION.
I SAY NOW
AND FOR THE RECORD
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
ORDERED THE ENTERPRISE
ACROSS THE NEUTRAL ZONE
ON HIS OWN INITIATIVE
AND HIS CRAVING FOR GLORY.
I'LL KILL YOU FOR THIS,
YOU TRAITOR!
I'LL KILL YOU!
HE IS NOT SANE.
ATTENTION, ENTERPRISE,
I AM SPEAKING TO YOU
FROM THE ROMULAN FLAGSHIP.
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
UNDER COMMAND OF CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK,
IS FORMALLY CHARGED
WITH ESPIONAGE.
THE TESTIMONY
OF FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
WAS HIGHLY INSTRUMENTAL
IN CONFIRMING
THIS INTRUSION
INTO ROMULAN SPACE
WAS NOT AN ACCIDENT.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK'S
TESTIMONY WAS SPECIFIC
THAT YOUR SHIP WAS NOT
UNDER ORDERS
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND
OR THE FEDERATION COUNCIL
TO PERFORM
SUCH A SPY MISSION.
IT WAS CAPTAIN KIRK
WHO WAS SOLELY RESPONSIBLE.
SINCE THE CREW HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO OBEY ORDERS,
THE CREW WILL NOT
BE HELD RESPONSIBLE.
THEREFORE, I AM ORDERING
ENGINEER SCOTT,
PRESENTLY IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
TO FOLLOW
THE ROMULAN FLAGSHIP
TO OUR HOME BASE.
YOU WILL THERE BE
PROCESSED AND RELEASED
TO FEDERATION COMMAND.
UNTIL JUDGMENT IS PASSED,
CAPTAIN KIRK WILL BE HELD
IN CONFINEMENT.
SECURITY, PUT OUR
TWO ROMULAN HOSTAGES
IN THE BRIG.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
GIVE ME A CHANNEL
TO THAT SHIP.
THE CHANNEL IS OPEN,
MR. SCOTT,
AND YOU ARE TIED IN.
THIS IS
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER SCOTT.
THE ENTERPRISE
TAKES NO ORDERS
EXCEPT THOSE
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
AND WE WILL STAY
RIGHT HERE
UNTIL HE RETURNS.
AND IF YOU MAKE
ANY ATTEMPT TO BOARD
OR COMMANDEER
THE ENTERPRISE,
IT WILL BE BLOWN TO BITS
ALONG WITH AS MANY OF YOU
AS WE CAN TAKE WITH US.
YOU HUMANS MAKE
A BRAVE NOISE.
THERE ARE WAYS
TO CONVINCE YOU
OF YOUR ERRORS.
[CLICK]
DID YOU HEAR THAT,
YOU COWARD?
YOU'VE BETRAYED EVERYTHING
OF VALUE YOU EVER KNEW.
DID YOU HEAR THE SOUND
OF HUMAN INTEGRITY?
TAKE HIM
TO THE SECURITY ROOM.
A VULCAN AMONG HUMANS...
LIVING,
WORKING WITH THEM...
I WOULD THINK
THE SITUATION WOULD BE
INTOLERABLE TO YOU.
I AM HALF VULCAN.
MY MOTHER
IS A HUMAN.
TO WHOM IS YOUR
ALLEGIANCE, THEN?
DO YOU CALL YOURSELF
TERRAN OR VULCAN?
VULCAN.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
A STARFLEET OFFICER, SPOCK?
18 YEARS.
AND YOU SERVE CAPTAIN KIRK.
DO YOU LIKE HIM?
DO YOU LIKE
YOUR SHIPMATES?
THE QUESTION
IS IRRELEVANT.
POSSIBLY.
BUT YOU ARE SUBORDINATE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK'S ORDERS,
EVEN TO HIS WHIMS.
MY DUTY AS AN OFFICER
IS TO OBEY HIM.
YOU ARE A SUPERIOR BEING.
WHY DO YOU NOT COMMAND?
I DO NOT DESIRE
A SHIP OF MY OWN.
OR IS IT THAT NO ONE
HAS OFFERED YOU, A VULCAN,
THAT OPPORTUNITY?
SUCH OPPORTUNITIES
ARE EXTREMELY RARE.
FOR SOMEONE
WITH YOUR CAPABILITIES
AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS,
OPPORTUNITIES ARE MADE...
AND WILL BE.
I WILL SEE TO THAT,
IF YOU WILL STOP LOOKING
ON THE FEDERATION
AS THE WHOLE UNIVERSE.
IT IS NOT, YOU KNOW.
THAT THOUGHT
HAS OCCASIONALLY
CROSSED MY MIND.
YOU MUST HAVE
YOUR OWN SHIP.
COMMANDER, SHALL WE
SPEAK PLAINLY?
IT IS YOU
WHO DESPERATELY
NEED A SHIP.
YOU WANT
THE ENTERPRISE.
OF COURSE.
IT WOULD BE
A GREAT ACHIEVEMENT FOR ME
TO BRING HOME
THE ENTERPRISE INTACT.
IT WOULD BROADEN THE SCOPE
OF MY POWERS GREATLY.
IT WOULD BE THE ACHIEVEMENT
OF A LIFETIME.
AND IT WOULD OPEN
EQUAL OPPORTUNITIES FOR YOU.
AAH!
Uhura:
BRIDGE TO DR. McCOY.
McCOY HERE.
DOCTOR, YOU MUST BEAM ABOARD
THE ROMULAN FLAGSHIP
IMMEDIATELY.
THERE'S BEEN AN INJURY.
I DON'T
MAKE HOUSE CALLS.
DOCTOR, IT'S CAPTAIN KIRK!
HE'LL RECOVER, BUT HE'LL NEED
FURTHER ATTENTION.
INFORM YOUR SUPERIOR.
[BEEPING]
YES?
I'LL COME THERE.
ATTEND ME.
I NEGLECTED TO MENTION,
I'LL EXPECT YOU FOR DINNER.
WE HAVE MUCH TO DISCUSS.
INDEED?
ALLOW ME TO--TO REPHRASE.
WILL YOU JOIN ME
FOR DINNER?
I AM HONORED,
COMMANDER.
ARE THE GUARDS
ALSO INVITED?
MR. SPOCK...
THAT CORRIDOR
IS FORBIDDEN TO ALL
BUT LOYAL ROMULANS.
OF COURSE.
I SHALL OBEY
YOUR RESTRICTIONS.
I HOPE THAT ONE DAY
THERE WILL BE NO NEED
FOR YOU TO OBSERVE
ANY RESTRICTIONS.
IT WOULD BE ILLOGICAL
TO ASSUME THAT
ALL CONDITIONS
REMAIN STABLE.
ARE YOU THE DOCTOR?
McCOY.
CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER.
CAPTAIN KIRK'S CONDITION?
WELL, YOU CAN SEE
FOR YOURSELF,
HE'S MENTALLY DEPRESSED,
PHYSICALLY WEAK,
DISORIENTED,
DISPLAYS FEELINGS
OF PERSECUTION
AND REBELLION.
THEN BY YOUR OWN STANDARDS
OF NORMALITY,
THIS MAN IS NOT
FULLY COMPETENT.
NO, NOT NOW.
MR. SPOCK HAS STATED
THAT HE BELIEVES
THE CAPTAIN HAD NO AUTHORITY
OR ORDER TO CROSS
THE NEUTRAL ZONE.
COULD THIS MENTAL
INCAPACITY
HAVE AFFLICTED HIM
EARLIER?
YES, IT'S POSSIBLE.
MR. SPOCK, THE DOCTOR
HAS NOW CONFIRMED
YOUR TESTIMONY
AS TO THE MENTAL STATE
OF YOUR CAPTAIN.
HE WAS AND IS UNFIT
TO CONTINUE IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
THAT DUTY HAS NOW
FALLEN ON YOU.
ARE YOU READY
TO EXERCISE THAT FUNCTION?
I AM READY.
SPOCK, I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
THERE'S NO PRICE
YOU COULD PAY
THAT WOULD MAKE HIM
SELL OUT.
THE MATTER IS NOT
OPEN FOR DISCUSSION,
DOCTOR.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
THE MATTER'S NOT OPEN FOR--
THAT'S ENOUGH, DOCTOR.
AS A PHYSICIAN, YOUR DUTY
IS TO SAVE LIVES.
MR. SPOCK'S DUTY
IS TO LEAD THE ENTERPRISE
AND ITS CREW
TO A SAFE HAVEN.
THERE IS NO
ALTERNATIVE, DOCTOR.
THE SAFETY
OF THE CREW IS NOW
THE PARAMOUNT ISSUE.
IT IS MISGUIDED LOYALTY
TO RESIST ANY FURTHER.
YOU TRAITOR.
I'LL KILL YOU.
I'LL KILL YOU!
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WHAT DID YOU DO?!
I WAS UNPREPARED
FOR HIS ATTACK.
I INSTINCTIVELY USED
THE VULCAN DEATH GRIP.
YOUR INSTINCTS ARE
STILL GOOD, MR. SPOCK.
THE CAPTAIN IS DEAD.
DOCTOR! DR. McCOY!
DR. McCOY!
I LEFT ORDERS THAT
NO ONE WAS TO COME IN HERE.
BUT HE'S ALIVE!
ALIVE!
WELL, NOW THAT YOU KNOW IT,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL ASSIST ME.
HAND ME
THE PHYSIO-STIMULATOR.
BUT HE WAS DEAD.
BUT THEIR DOCTORS
CERTIFIED HE WAS DEAD.
SPOCK GAVE HIM
A NERVE PINCH
TO SIMULATE DEATH.
THEN MR. SPOCK
ISN'T A TRAITOR,
AND YOU KNEW THAT
ALL THE TIME
AND YOU DIDN'T--
I DIDN'T KNOW IT
UNTIL I BEAMED ABOARD
THE ROMULAN SHIP.
JIM AND SPOCK WERE OPERATING
UNDER FEDERATION ORDERS.
OHH...
OHH.
MY NECK FEELS LIKE
IT'S BEEN TWISTED OFF.
THAT'S THE VULCAN
DEATH GRIP FOR YOU.
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS A VULCAN DEATH GRIP.
AH, BUT THE ROMULANS
DON'T KNOW THAT.
SURE FOOLED
THE DOCTORS.
YOU TOOK A BIG CHANCE
THAT THEY DIDN'T START
AN AUTOPSY.
AS FAR AS THE REST OF
THE CREW IS CONCERNED,
I'M STILL DEAD.
WHY?
THAT'S WHAT THIS WHOLE
MASQUERADE WAS ABOUT--
TO KEEP THE ENTERPRISE
AND THE FEDERATION
OFF THE HOOK.
SO THAT IF
ANYTHING WENT WRONG,
YOU WOULD BE
THE ONE TO BLAME.
BONES, I WANT YOU
TO PREPARE FOR SURGERY.
WHAT FOR?
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
SICK BAY TO BRIDGE.
SCOTT HERE, DOCTOR.
MR. SCOTT, WILL YOU
REPORT TO SICK BAY.
SICK BAY?
I CAN'T LEAVE THE BRIDGE
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
YOU HAVE TO.
IT'S URGENT.
WE'RE SURROUNDED
BY ENEMY VESSELS
READY TO ATTACK US.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYTHING
MORE URGENT THAN THAT.
WELL, I DO.
MR. SCOTT, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR.
IT BETTER BE IMPORTANT.
SCOTT OUT.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR,
WHAT'S SO URGENT THAT--
CAPTAIN?
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YES.
WELL, YOU LOOK LIKE
THE DEVIL HIMSELF,
BUT AS LONG AS
YOU'RE ALIVE.
WHAT'S IT ALL ABOUT?
ARE THOSE ROMULAN OFFICERS
STILL ABOARD THE SHIP?
THEY'RE IN THE BRIG,
SIR.
I'LL NEED
A ROMULAN UNIFORM.
AH...
AYE.
IT'LL BE A PLEASURE.
I'VE HAD SPECIAL VULCAN DISHES
PREPARED FOR YOU.
I HOPE THEY'RE TO YOUR LIKING.
I AM VERY FLATTERED,
COMMANDER.
THERE'S NO DOUBT
THAT THE CUISINE
ABOARD YOUR VESSEL
IS FAR SUPERIOR TO
THAT OF THE ENTERPRISE.
IT IS, INDEED,
A VERY POWERFUL
RECRUITING INDUCEMENT.
WE HAVE OTHER
INDUCEMENTS.
WHAT THE DEVIL
IS SPOCK DOING?
WHAT'S DELAYING HIM?
I WISH I KNEW.
SCOTTY, ARE YOU SURE
WE HAVE A CLEAR CHANNEL
TO SPOCK?
AYE, SIR.
NO DOUBT OF IT.
THEN WE CAN'T WAIT
ANY LONGER.
PREPARE TO BEAM ME
ABOARD THE FLAGSHIP.
BUT MR. SPOCK HASN'T SENT
THE PROPER COORDINATES.
IT CAN'T BE HELPED, SCOTTY.
YOU'RE TAKING
AN AWFUL CHANCE, JIM.
JUST DON'T PUT ME
INSIDE A BULKHEAD. ENERGIZE.
CENTURION, I'M SORRY.
NO ONE IS ALLOWED--
I HAVE JUST EFFECTED AN ESCAPE
FROM A FEDERATION VESSEL.
I HAVE IMPORTANT INFORMATION
FOR SUBCOMMANDER TAL.
WHERE IS HE?
HE IS IN CONTROL CENTRAL,
CENTURION.
GOOD. I SHALL REMEMBER
TO MENTION
YOUR ALERTNESS TO HIM.
RETURN TO YOUR DUTY.
THANK YOU,
CENTURION.
YOU HAVE NOTHING
IN STARFLEET
TO WHICH TO RETURN.
I OFF--
WE...
OFFER YOU
AN ALTERNATIVE.
WE WILL FIND
A PLACE FOR YOU,
IF YOU WISH IT.
A PLACE?
MM-HMM.
WITH ME.
ROMULAN WOMEN ARE NOT
LIKE VULCAN FEMALES.
WE ARE NOT
DEDICATED TO...
PURE LOGIC
AND THE STERILITY
OF NON-EMOTION.
OUR PEOPLE ARE WARRIORS.
OFTEN SAVAGE.
BUT WE ARE ALSO
MANY OTHER PLEASANT THINGS.
I WAS NOT AWARE
OF THAT ASPECT
OF ROMULAN SOCIETY.
AS A VULCAN,
YOU WILL STUDY IT.
AS A HUMAN,
YOU WOULD FIND WAYS
TO APPRECIATE IT.
PLEASE BELIEVE ME.
I DO...
APPRECIATE IT.
I AM SO GLAD.
NOW, ONE FINAL STEP
TO MAKE THE OCCASION COMPLETE.
YOU WILL LEAD
A SMALL PARTY OF ROMULANS
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE,
AND THERE YOU WILL TAKE
YOUR RIGHTFUL PLACE
AS ITS COMMANDER,
AND YOU WILL LEAD THE SHIP
TO A ROMULAN PORT,
WITH MY FLAGSHIP
AT ITS SIDE.
YES, OF COURSE.
BUT NOT
JUST THIS MOMENT.
AN HOUR FROM NOW
WILL DO...
EVEN BETTER.
WOULD IT NOT...
COMMANDER?
YES.
YES, IT WILL...
MR. SPOCK.
YOU DO KNOW
I HAVE A FIRST NAME.
I WAS BEGINNING
TO WONDER.
WELL, I DO.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HEAR IT?
HOW RARE...
AND HOW BEAUTIFUL...
BUT SO INCONGRUOUS
WHEN SPOKEN BY
A SOLDIER.
IF YOU WILL
GIVE ME A MOMENT,
THE SOLDIER WILL
TRANSFORM HERSELF...
INTO A WOMAN.
SPOCK TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, ARE YOU PREPARED
TO BEAM OVER?
I'M ALREADY ON BOARD, SPOCK.
DO YOU HAVE
THE INFORMATION?
YES, CAPTAIN.
THE CLOAKING DEVICE
IS IN AN AREA NEAR
THE COMMANDER'S QUARTERS.
IT IS CLOSELY GUARDED
AND OFF-LIMITS TO ALL
BUT AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL.
WHAT IS
YOUR PRESENT LOCATION?
SUBCOMMANDER TAL,
I'M RECEIVING
AN ALIEN TRANSMISSION
FROM WITHIN
OUR VESSEL, SIR.
ALIEN?
ARE YOU CERTAIN?
YES, SUBCOMMANDER.
I MUST KNOW THE SOURCE!
TRIANGULATING NOW, SIR.
SPOCK, I'LL GET
THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
WILL YOU BE ABLE TO GET
BACK TO THE ENTERPRISE
WITHOUT ATTRACTING
THEIR ATTENTION?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
AT PRESENT,
I AM RATHER HEAVILY--
IS MY...
ATTIRE NOW
MORE APPROPRIATE...
MR. SPOCK?
COMMANDER, YOUR ATTIRE IS
NOT ONLY MORE APPROPRIATE,
IT SHOULD ACTUALLY
STIMULATE OUR CONVERSATION.
CENTURION,
HAVE YOU CLEARANCE
FOR THIS AREA?
I DO NOT
RECOGNIZE YOU.
THERE'S AN INTRUDER
ABOARD.
HAS SOMEONE TRIED
TO GAIN ENTRANCE THERE?
OVER THERE!
I MUST SEE
YOUR AUTHORIZATION--
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE...
THAT I CAN BE
SO MOVED...
BY THE TOUCH
OF AN ALIEN HAND.
I MUST CONFESS
THAT I, TOO...
AM MOVED EMOTIONALLY.
I KNOW IT IS ILLOGICAL.
MR. SPOCK...
WE MUSTN'T QUESTION
WHAT WE TRULY FEEL.
ACCEPT WHAT IS HAPPENING
BETWEEN US,
EVEN AS I DO.
[BEEP]
COMMANDER.
PERMISSION
TO ENTER.
NOT NOW, TAL.
IT IS URGENT,
COMMANDER.
ENTER.
COMMANDER,
WE HAVE INTERCEPTED
AN ALIEN TRANSMISSION.
LOCATE ITS SOURCE.
WE HAVE, COMMANDER.
THIS ROOM.
THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
BRING HIM.
HALT.
DON'T MOVE.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN HERE?
THERE'S AN ENEMY SPY
ABOARD.
HE'LL BE AFTER
THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
DROP YOUR WEAPON.
SCOTTY...
ENERGIZE.
BUT, SIR,
WHAT ABOUT MR. SPOCK?
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO HOPE
HE CAN BUY US TIME
TO GET THIS CLOAKING
DEVICE INSTALLED.
IT'LL HAVE TO BE HOOKED IN
TO OUR DEFLECTOR SHIELD CONTROL.
I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
CAN YOU DO IT?
YOU HAVE 15 MINUTES,
SCOTTY.
COMMANDER, THE CLOAKING
DEVICE IS GONE.
FULL ALERT.
SEARCH ALL DECKS.
THAT WILL BE PROFITLESS,
COMMANDER.
I DO NOT BELIEVE
YOU WILL FIND IT.
YOU MUST BE MAD.
I ASSURE YOU...
I AM QUITE SANE.
WHY WOULD YOU
DO THIS TO ME?
WHAT ARE YOU
THAT YOU COULD DO THIS?
FIRST OFFICER...
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
WHAT IS YOUR PRESENT
FORM OF EXECUTION?
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5027.4.
COMMANDER SCOTT
HAS LESS THAN 15 MINUTES
TO INSTALL THE ROMULAN'S
CLOAKING DEVICE
AND GET IT WORKING.
I HOPE MR. SPOCK CAN
BUY US THE TIME WE NEED.
CAPTAIN!
YOU'RE ALIVE!
THEY SAID
YOU'D BEEN KILLED, SIR.
THE REPORT WAS PREMATURE.
CAPTAIN, YOUR EARS.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE'LL DISCUSS IT LATER.
MR. SULU,
LAY IN A COURSE FOR HOME.
MR. CHEKOV,
TAKE THE SENSORS.
MR. SPOCK IS STILL ABOARD
THE ROMULAN FLAGSHIP.
I WANT HIS BODY READINGS
PINPOINTED AND ISOLATED.
THAT WAS NOT A REQUEST,
GENTLEMEN.
AYE, SIR.
RETURN TO YOUR STATION,
SUBCOMMANDER.
THE BOARDING ACTION
ON THE ENTERPRISE
WILL BEGIN
WITH MY COMMAND.
IF THEY RESIST,
DESTROY HER.
EXECUTION
OF STATE CRIMINALS
IS BOTH PAINFUL
AND UNPLEASANT.
I BELIEVE THE DETAILS
ARE UNNECESSARY.
THE SENTENCE
WILL BE CARRIED OUT
IMMEDIATELY AFTER THE CHARGES
HAVE BEEN RECORDED.
I DEMAND THE RIGHT
OF STATEMENT FIRST.
YOU UNDERSTAND
ROMULAN TRADITION WELL.
THE RIGHT IS GRANTED.
THANK YOU.
I SHALL NOT REQUIRE
MUCH TIME,
NO MORE THAN...
20 MINUTES,
I SHOULD SAY.
IT SHOULD TAKE
LESS TIME THAN THAT
TO FIND YOUR ALLY WHO
STOLE THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
YOU WILL NOT DIE ALONE.
RECORDING THE ROMULAN
RIGHT OF STATEMENT.
PROCEED, COMMANDER SPOCK.
MY CRIME IS SABOTAGE.
I FREELY ADMIT MY GUILT.
THE OATH I SWORE
AS A STARFLEET OFFICER
IS BOTH SPECIFIC
AND BINDING.
AS LONG AS I
WEAR THE UNIFORM,
MY DUTY IS TO PROTECT
THE SECURITY
OF THE FEDERATION.
CLEARLY, YOUR
NEW CLOAKING DEVICE
IS A THREAT
TO THAT SECURITY.
I CARRIED OUT MY DUTY.
EVERYONE
CARRIES OUT HIS DUTY.
YOU STATE THE OBVIOUS,
SPOCK.
THERE IS NO REGULATION
REGARDING THE CONTENT
OF MY STATEMENT.
MAY I CONTINUE?
VERY WELL.
YOUR 20 MINUTES
IS ALMOST UP.
MR. CHEKOV,
THERE'S ONLY ONE VULCAN
ABOARD THAT SHIP.
HE SHOULD BE EASY ENOUGH
TO LOCATE.
ROMULANS AND VULCANS APPEAR
TO READ ALMOST EXACTLY ALIKE.
THERE IS JUST
A SLIGHT DIFFERENCE WHICH--
GOT HIM, SIR.
FEED THE COORDINATES
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
ON THE DOUBLE.
HAVE THEM PREPARE TO BEAM
HIM ABOARD ON MY SIGNAL.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
MR. SCOTT IS ON THE INTERCOM
FOR YOU, SIR.
GO AHEAD, SCOTTY.
I'VE GOT THAT DEVICE
INSTALLED,
BUT BLESS ME
IF I KNOW WHETHER
IT'S GOING TO WORK.
IT'S THE BIGGEST GUESS
I'VE EVER MADE.
STAND BY, SCOTTY.
SIR, TRANSPORTER ROOM
HAS THE COORDINATES
AND IS READY
FOR BEAMING.
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
BEAM MR. SPOCK ABOARD.
BEYOND
THE HISTORIC TRADITION
OF VULCAN LOYALTY,
THERE IS ALSO
THE COMBINED
ROMULAN-VULCAN HISTORY
OF OBEDIENCE TO DUTY.
TRANSPORTER ROOM REPORTS
MR. SPOCK ABOARD, SIR,
AND THE ROMULAN COMMANDER.
THE COMMANDER?
AYE, SIR.
HA HA! ALL RIGHT.
HAVE THEM REPORT TO
THE BRIDGE ON THE DOUBLE.
MR. SULU, TAKE US AWAY
FROM THE ROMULAN.
WARP FACTOR 9.
SUBCOMMANDER,
THE ENEMY VESSEL
IS MOVING AWAY
AT EXTREME SPEED, SIR.
ALERT ALL VESSELS.
WEAPONS OFFICER,
BRING MAIN BATTERIES TO
BEAR ON THE ENTERPRISE.
HOLDING AT WARP 9, SIR.
SCOTTY, YOU BETTER
SWITCH ON THAT DEVICE.
I DID, SIR.
IT'S NOT WORKING.
I WOULD GIVE YOU
CREDIT, CAPTAIN,
FOR GETTING THIS FAR,
BUT YOU WILL BE DEAD
IN A MOMENT,
AND THE CREDIT
WOULD BE GRATUITOUS.
LIEUTENANT,
OPEN A CHANNEL TO
THE ROMULAN VESSEL.
AYE, SIR.
I HAVE
SUBCOMMANDER TAL, SIR.
ESTABLISH TWO-WAY
VISUAL CONTACT.
WE HAVE YOU UNDER
OUR WEAPONS, ENTERPRISE.
YOU CANNOT ESCAPE.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
HOLD YOUR FIRE.
WE HAVE YOUR COMMANDER
ABOARD.
COMMANDER?
DESTROY THIS VESSEL.
I GAVE YOU A DIRECT
COMMAND!
BREAK CONTACT!
TAL!
HELMSMAN, FLANK SPEED.
WEAPONS OFFICER, STAND BY
TO FIRE MAIN BATTERIES
AS SOON AS WE REACH
OPTIMUM RANGE.
SCOTTY, WE'RE
RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
CAPTAIN, I'M WORKING
AS FAST AS I CAN.
YOU SEE, CAPTAIN?
YOUR EFFORT
IS BEING WASTED.
MR. SPOCK, DISTANCE
FROM THE ROMULAN VESSEL?
150,000 KILOMETERS,
CAPTAIN,
AND CLOSING VERY RAPIDLY.
STAND BY, PHASERS.
COMMANDER, YOU'LL FORGIVE ME
IF I PUT UP A FIGHT.
OF COURSE.
IT'S EXPECTED.
100,000 KILOMETERS.
THEY SHOULD
COMMENCE FIRING AT US
WITHIN THE NEXT
12.7 SECONDS.
SCOTTY...
IT'S READY NOW,
CAPTAIN,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER OUR CIRCUITS
CAN HANDLE THIS
ALIEN CONTRAPTION.
PULL THE SWITCH.
IT'LL LIKELY OVERLOAD.
THROW THE SWITCH.
WEAPONS OFFICER,
COMMENCE FI--
GONE.
THEY HAVE
THE CLOAKING DEVICE!
QUICKLY,
COMPUTE ENEMY COURSE
FROM LAST POSITION
YES, SIR.
AND OPEN FIRE!
MR. SULU, COME ABOUT.
318 MARK 7.
318 MARK 7, SIR.
EXECUTING.
THE CLOAKING DEVICE
IS WORKING PERFECTLY,
AND THE COMMANDER
HAS INFORMED ME
THAT EVEN
THE ROMULAN SENSORS
CANNOT TRACK A VESSEL
SO EQUIPPED.
THANK YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
CANCEL RED ALERT.
WE'LL LET YOU OFF
AT THE NEAREST
FEDERATION OUTPOST.
YOU ARE VERY GENEROUS,
CAPTAIN.
IF I MAY BE TAKEN
TO YOUR BRIG,
I WILL TAKE MY PLACE
AS YOUR PRISONER.
MR. SPOCK WILL HAVE
THE HONOR OF ESCORTING
YOU TO YOUR QUARTERS.
CAPTAIN.
COMMANDER.
DECK 2.
IT IS REGRETTABLE
THAT YOU WERE MADE
AN UNWILLING PASSENGER.
IT WAS NOT INTENTIONAL.
ALL THE FEDERATION WANTED
WAS THE CLOAKING DEVICE.
THE FEDERATION?
AND WHAT DID YOU WANT?
IT WAS MY ONLY INTEREST
WHEN I BOARDED
YOUR VESSEL.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
ALL YOU CAME AWAY WITH.
YOU UNDERESTIMATE
YOURSELF, COMMANDER.
YOU REALIZE
THAT VERY SOON
WE WILL LEARN
TO PENETRATE
THE CLOAKING DEVICE
YOU STOLE.
OBVIOUSLY.
MILITARY SECRETS ARE
THE MOST FLEETING OF ALL.
I HOPE THAT YOU AND I
EXCHANGED SOMETHING
MORE PERMANENT.
IT WAS YOUR CHOICE.
IT WAS THE ONLY CHOICE
POSSIBLE.
YOU WOULD NOT RESPECT
ANY OTHER.
IT WILL BE OUR SECRET.
ENTERING NEUTRAL ZONE,
CAPTAIN.
VERY GOOD, MR. CHEKOV.
THANK YOU, MR. LESLIE.
SICK BAY TO BRIDGE.
WHAT IS IT, BONES?
IF ALL THE SHOUTING'S OVER
UP THERE,
I'D LIKE FOR YOU
TO REPORT TO SICK BAY.
WHAT FOR?
WELL, YOU'RE DUE IN SURGERY.
I'M GOING TO BOB YOUR EARS.
CAPTAIN...
PLEASE GO.
SOMEHOW THEY DO NOT LOOK
AESTHETICALLY AGREEABLE
ON HUMANS.
WELL, ARE YOU COMING, JIM,
OR DO YOU WANT
TO GO THROUGH LIFE
LOOKING LIKE
YOUR FIRST OFFICER?
I'M ON MY WAY.