LOOK AT THOSE
PINE TREES.
AND THAT LAKE.
I SWEAR THAT'S
HONEYSUCKLE I SMELL.
I SWEAR THAT'S A LITTLE
ORANGE BLOSSOM THROWN IN.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
GROWTH,
EXACTLY LIKE THAT
OF EARTH,
ON A PLANET
HALF A GALAXY AWAY.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS
ON SUCH DUPLICATION?
ASTRONOMICAL, CAPTAIN.
THE RELATIVE SIZE,
AGE, AND COMPOSITION
OF THIS PLANET
MAKES IT HIGHLY IMPROBABLE
THAT IT WOULD EVOLVE
SIMILARLY TO EARTH
IN ANY WAY.
WHAT IN BLAZES
IS THAT?
Kirk:
ANALYSIS, SPOCK.
AN ALIEN METAL
OF SOME KIND.
AN ALLOY RESISTANT
TO PROBE.
READINGS CAN'T EVEN
MEASURE ITS AGE ACCURATELY.
THESE INCISED SYMBOLS
ARE FASCINATING,
EVIDENTLY
SOME FORM OF WRITING.
ANY THEORIES
ABOUT WHAT IT IS?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
STRUCTURES
OF THIS COMPLEXITY
REQUIRE EXTREMELY
SOPHISTICATED BUILDING
APPARATUS,
THE KIND USUALLY
FOUND IN CULTURES
SURPASSING
OR EQUALING OUR OWN.
MEADOWS
AND NO METEOR CRATERS?
THE WHOLE PLACE IS AN ENIGMA,
BIOLOGICALLY AND CULTURALLY.
WHAT'S THE NEAREST
CONCENTRATION OF LIFE
FORMS, MR. SPOCK?
BEARING 117, MARK 4.
AND HOW MUCH TIME
DID YOU SAY WE HAVE
TO INVESTIGATE?
IF WE ARE TO DIVERT
THE ASTEROID
WHICH IS ON A COLLISION
COURSE WITH THIS PLANET,
WE MUST WARP OUT OF ORBIT
WITHIN 30 MINUTES.
EVERY SECOND WE DELAY
ARRIVING AT THE
DEFLECTION POINT
COMPOUNDS THE PROBLEM,
PERHAPS PAST SOLUTION.
YOU DID SAY 30 MINUTES?
YES, SIR.
THEN LET'S GO.
LET'S FIND OUT
WHAT LIFE FORMS
ARE BLESSED BY
THIS ENVIRONMENT.
WHY, THEY LOOK LIKE--
I'D SWEAR THEY'RE
AMERICAN INDIANS.
THEY ARE, DOCTOR.
A MIXTURE OF NAVAJO,
MOHICAN, AND DELAWARE,
I BELIEVE.
ALL AMONG
THE MORE ADVANCED
AND PEACEFUL TRIBES.
IT'S LIKE
DISCOVERING ATLANTIS...
OR SHANGRI-LA.
MR. SPOCK,
IS IT POSSIBLE
THERE'S A MORE EVOLVED
CIVILIZATION SOMEWHERE ELSE
ON THIS PLANET,
ONE CAPABLE OF BUILDING
THAT OBELISK
OR DEVELOPING
A DEFLECTOR SYSTEM?
HIGHLY IMPROBABLE,
CAPTAIN.
SENSOR PROBES
INDICATE ONLY ONE TYPE
OF LIFE FORM HERE.
SHOULDN'T WE CONTACT THEM,
JIM, TELL THEM?
TELL THEM WHAT?
THAT AN ASTEROID'S COMING
TO SMASH THEIR WORLD
INTO ATOMS?
TOO PRIMITIVE
TO GRASP THE CONCEPT
OF SPACE FLIGHT,
DOCTOR.
OUR APPEARANCE HERE
WOULD ONLY SERVE
TO CONFUSE
AND FRIGHTEN THEM.
WE'VE GOT A JOB TO DO.
LET'S GET BACK
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, JIM?
WHAT?
OH, NOTHING.
JUST SO PEACEFUL,
UNCOMPLICATED.
NO PROBLEMS, NO...
COMMAND DECISIONS.
JUST...LIVING.
TYPICAL HUMAN REACTION
TO AN IDYLLIC
NATURAL SETTING.
BACK IN THE 20th CENTURY,
WE REFERRED TO IT
AS THE TAHITI SYNDROME.
IT'S PARTICULARLY COMMON
TO OVERPRESSURED
LEADER TYPES,
LIKE STARSHIP CAPTAINS.
AH, TAHITI SYNDROME.
LET'S GO TAKE CARE
OF THAT ASTEROID.
BUT FIRST,
I WANT ANOTHER LOOK
AT THAT OBELISK.
DOCTOR?
YES?
I SUGGEST THAT
ANY FURTHER RESEARCH
ON YOUR PART
BE DELAYED UNTIL
AFTER WE HAVE DIVERTED
THE ASTEROID.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
Scott: YES, SIR.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 4842.6.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
COMMANDING.
NUMEROUS SEARCH PARTIES
AND REPEATED SENSOR PROBES
OF THE AREA
HAVE FAILED TO LOCATE
CAPTAIN KIRK.
SPOCK TO ENTERPRISE.
Scott: ENTERPRISE.
COME IN, MR. SPOCK.
PREPARE TO BEAM US UP,
MR. SCOTT.
WE'RE WARPING OUT OF ORBIT.
LEAVING? YOU CAN'T
BE SERIOUS, SPOCK.
DOCTOR, THAT ASTEROID
IS ALMOST AS LARGE
AS YOUR EARTH'S MOON.
FAR ENOUGH AWAY,
THE ANGLE NECESSARY
TO DIVERT IT ENOUGH
TO AVOID DESTRUCTION
IS MINUTE,
BUT AS THE ASTEROID
APPROACHES THIS PLANET,
THE ANGLE BECOMES SO GREAT
THAT EVEN THE POWER
OF A STARSHIP--
THE DEVIL
WITH AN ASTEROID!
IT WON'T GET HERE
FOR 2 MONTHS, SPOCK!
IF WE ARRIVE AT THE
DEFLECTION POINT IN TIME,
IT MAY NOT GET HERE
AT ALL.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WHAT ABOUT JIM?
ONCE THE ASTEROID
HAS BEEN DIVERTED,
WE'LL RETURN HERE
AND RESUME THE SEARCH.
THAT MAY BE
HOURS FROM NOW.
HE MAY BE INJURED
OR DYING.
DOCTOR...
ASSUME THIS IS
THE PLANET WE'RE ON.
THIS IS THE APPROACHING
ASTEROID.
IF WE DON'T GET
TO THAT DEFLECTION
POINT IN TIME,
IT WILL BECOME
PHYSICALLY IMPOSSIBLE
TO DIVERT THIS ASTEROID.
IN THAT CASE, EVERYONE
ON THIS PLANET WILL DIE,
INCLUDING THE CAPTAIN.
CAN A FEW MORE MINUTES
MATTER, SPOCK?
IN THE TIME
IT HAS TAKEN ME
TO EXPLAIN THE PROBLEM,
THE ASTEROID
HAS MOVED FROM HERE
TO HERE.
THE LONGER WE DELAY,
THE LESS THE LIKELIHOOD
OF BEING ABLE
TO DIVERT IT.
BEAM US UP, MR. SCOTT.
[THINKING]
WHERE AM I?
WHAT PLACE IS THIS?
WHAT ARE THESE?
I FEEL I SHOULD KNOW.
THEY'RE FAMILIAR
AND YET UNFAMILIAR.
HOW DID I GET HERE?
WHO AM I?
TRY TO REMEMBER.
WAIT.
WHO ARE YOU?
WE ARE YOUR PEOPLE.
WE'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR YOU TO COME TO US.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 4843.6.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
COMMANDING.
WE'VE BEEN EN ROUTE
TO THE ASTEROID
FOR SEVERAL HOURS.
OUR DELAY
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE
HAS MADE IT IMPERATIVE
THAT WE PROCEED
AT MAXIMUM WARP SPEED
FOR A PERIOD WHICH EXCEEDS
THE RECOMMENDED SAFETY MARGIN.
I CAN'T GIVE YOU WARP 9
MUCH LONGER, MR. SPOCK.
THESE ENGINES ARE BEGINNING
TO SHOW SIGNS OF STRESS.
STRESS OR NOT,
WE CANNOT REDUCE SPEED.
I DO NOT INTEND TO MISS
THAT DEFLECTION POINT.
ALL RIGHT. BUT WE'RE
MOVING FURTHER
INTO THE DANGER RANGE
ALL THE TIME.
IF THESE CIRCUITS--
OBJECTION NOTED,
MR. SCOTT.
CARRY ON.
MIRAMANEE HAS SAID
THAT YOU APPEARED TO HER
AND TO HER HANDMAIDEN
FROM THE WALLS
OF THE TEMPLE,
JUST AS OUR LEGEND
FORETELLS.
WE DO NOT DOUBT
THE WORDS
OF OUR PRIESTESS,
BUT THESE
ARE TROUBLED TIMES
AND WE MUST BE SURE.
I'LL ANSWER ANYTHING
I CAN,
BUT AS I TOLD YOU...
MANY THINGS
ARE STRANGE TO ME.
HE KNOWS NOTHING
OF OUR DANGER.
HOW COULD HE SAVE US?
IT IS AGAINST CUSTOM
TO INTERRUPT A TRIBAL ELDER
AT COUNCIL,
EVEN FOR THE MEDICINE CHIEF.
ELDER,
WORDS WILL NOT SAVE US
WHEN THE SKIES DARKEN.
WE MUST BE CERTAIN.
I SAY HE MUST PROVE
HE IS A GOD.
OUR SKIES HAVE DARKENED
3 TIMES
SINCE THE HARVEST,
THE LAST TIME
WORST OF ALL.
OUR LEGEND PREDICTS
SUCH DANGER
AND PROMISES
THAT THE WISE ONES
WHO PLANTED US HERE
WILL SEND A GOD
TO SAVE US,
ONE WHO CAN ROUSE
THE TEMPLE SPIRIT
AND MAKE THE SKY
GROW QUIET.
CAN YOU DO THIS?
I CAME FROM THE TEMPLE
AS MIRAMANEE SAID,
AND IT WAS
A BEGINNING FOR ME...HERE.
BUT I CAME FROM THE SKY...
TOO.
ONLY I...CAN'T REMEMBER.
I...
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
SALISH, A TERRIBLE THING
HAS HAPPENED.
THE BOY WAS ATTENDING
THE FISH NETS.
HE BECAME ENTANGLED IN THEM
AND SANK TO THE BOTTOM
OF THE RIVER.
LUMO BROUGHT HIM UP QUICKLY,
BUT HE DOESN'T MOVE.
THERE IS NO SOUND
IN THE BODY.
THERE IS NO LIGHT
IN THE EYES.
HE WILL MOVE NO MORE.
WAIT A MOMENT.
WAIT!
[COUGHS]
HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT NOW.
MY PEOPLE ARE GRATEFUL.
IT'S A SIMPLE TECHNIQUE.
IT GOES WAY BACK...
WAY BACK...
ONLY A GOD
CAN BREATHE LIFE
INTO THE DEAD.
DO YOU STILL QUESTION?
GIVE HIM
THE MEDICINE BADGE.
Chekov:
DEFLECTION POINT MINUS 7.
Spock:
FULL POWER, MR. SCOTT.
THE RELAYS WILL REJECT
THE OVERLOAD, MR. SPOCK.
THEN BYPASS THE RELAYS,
GO TO MANUAL CONTROL.
DO THAT, WE'LL BURN
OUT THE ENGINES.
I WANT FULL POWER,
MR. SCOTT.
AYE, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, YOU LOVELIES,
HOLD TOGETHER.
FULL POWER,
MR. SPOCK.
MAGNIFICATION FACTOR 12,
MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
DEFLECTION POINT
MINUS 4.
ALL ENGINES STOPPED.
HOLD POSITION HERE.
ALL ENGINES STOPPED, SIR.
PREPARE TO ACTIVATE
DEFLECTORS.
AYE, SIR.
POWER DROPPING, SIR.
ENGINEERING,
MAINTAIN FULL POWER.
FULL POWER.
DILITHIUM CRYSTAL
CIRCUIT'S FAILING, SIR.
WE'LL HAVE TO REPLACE IT.
NOT NOW.
ZERO!
DEFLECTION POINT...
NOW, SIR.
ACTIVATE DEFLECTORS.
POWER DROPPING, SIR.
DEGREE OF DEFLECTION,
MR. SULU.
NOT ENOUGH, MR. SPOCK.
IT'S ONLY .0013 DEGREES.
RECIRCUIT POWER
TO ENGINES.
MAXIMUM SPEED,
HEADING 37 MARK 010.
AYE, SIR.
THAT HEADING WILL
PUT US DIRECTLY IN
THE ASTEROID'S PATH, SIR.
CORRECT, MR. CHEKOV.
I INTEND
TO RETREAT IN FRONT
OF THAT ASTEROID
UNTIL WE CAN
EMPLOY ALL POWER
ON PHASER BEAMS.
WHAT FOR?
TO DESTROY IT.
A NARROW BEAM
CONCENTRATED
ON A SINGLE SPOT
WILL SPLIT
THAT MASS.
IT MIGHT ALSO
CRIPPLE THE SHIP,
AND WE WOULD BE CRUSHED
BY THE ASTEROID.
INCORRECT. WE'LL STILL BE
ABLE TO GET OUT OF ITS PATH
BY USING IMPULSE POWER.
BUT JIM WON'T BE ABLE
TO GET OUT OF ITS PATH.
THAT, DOCTOR, IS
ANOTHER CALCULATED RISK
WE MUST TAKE.
MIRAMANEE...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I MUST SEE
TO THE NEEDS OF THE GOD,
AS IS MY DUTY.
YOU SHOULD BE WORKING
ON OUR RITUAL CLOAK.
THERE WILL BE NO RITUAL
BETWEEN US NOW, SALISH.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WE CANNOT GO
AGAINST TRADITION.
IT IS BECAUSE
OF TRADITION THAT
I CANNOT MARRY YOU.
BUT YOU ARE
PROMISED TO ME.
THAT WAS BEFORE HE CAME.
TRIBAL PRIESTESS
AND MEDICINE CHIEF
ARE ALWAYS JOINED.
HE IS MEDICINE CHIEF NOW.
SALISH, CHOOSE ANOTHER.
ANY MAIDEN WOULD BE
HONORED TO JOIN WITH YOU.
I...
WISH NO OTHER.
YOU HAVE NO CHOICE.
MIRAMANEE...
IF YOU COULD CHOOSE...
WOULD YOU CHOOSE ME?
PERHAPS YOU WOULD LIKE
TO BATHE NOW.
MIRAMANEE...
TELL ME
ABOUT THE WISE ONES.
TELL?
BUT A GOD KNOWS
EVERYTHING.
NOT THIS ONE.
TELL ME.
THE WISE ONES
BROUGHT US HERE
FROM FAR AWAY.
THEY CHOSE
A MEDICINE CHIEF
TO KEEP THE SECRET
OF THE TEMPLE
AND TO USE IT
WHEN THE SKY DARKENS.
SECRETS OF THE TEMPLE?
THERE ARE NO LACINGS.
HOW IS THIS THING
REMOVED?
THE SECRETS
WERE PASSED ON
FROM FATHER TO SON.
YES. HOW DOES THIS OPEN?
WELL, WHY DOESN'T
SALISH USE IT?
WHY ARE THE PEOPLE
IN DANGER?
HIS FATHER DID NOT WISH
TO SHARE HIS POWER TOO SOON.
HE DIED BEFORE
HE TOLD SALISH THE SECRET.
OUR PEOPLE REJOICE
AND WISH TO HONOR
YOUR NAME,
BUT I DID NOT KNOW
WHAT YOU WISH TO BE CALLED.
WHAT MAY I TELL THEM?
KIR...
KIR...KIROK?
HAVE WE DISPLEASED YOU?
NO, NO,
EVERYTHING IS FINE.
THEN IT MUST BE OURSELVES,
THE WAY WE LIVE.
PERHAPS WE HAVE NOT
IMPROVED AS QUICKLY
AS THE WISE ONES WISHED.
YOUR LAND IS RICH,
YOUR PEOPLE HAPPY.
WHO COULD BE
DISPLEASED WITH THAT?
BUT THERE IS SOMETHING.
TELL US.
WE WILL CHANGE IT.
I CAN'T
TELL YOU ANYTHING.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU
IS THAT I'M...
HAPPY AND PEACEFUL
HERE.
I'M NOT SURE,
BUT I THINK
I'VE NEVER FELT
THAT WAY BEFORE.
WHY ARE THEY SO SURE
I CAN HELP THEM?
WELL, YOU CAME
FROM THE STONE METAL.
DID YOU NOT BRING LIFE
TO THE CHILD?
YES, BUT I...
I NEED TIME TO REMEMBER.
HERE THERE IS MUCH TIME.
FOR EVERYTHING.
COORDINATES, MR. CHEKOV.
TAU 8.7.
BETA .041.
THAT IS OUR TARGET--
THE ASTEROID'S
WEAKEST POINT.
ALMOST DEAD CENTER, SIR.
LOCK ALL PHASERS
ON THAT MARK.
MAXIMUM INTENSITY,
NARROW BEAM.
I WANT TO SPLIT
THAT FISSURE WIDE OPEN.
YOU SOUND LIKE
YOU'RE CUTTING A DIAMOND.
VERY ASTUTE, DOCTOR.
ALL PHASERS
LOCKED, SIR.
WE'LL FIRE IN SEQUENCE
AND CONTINUE FIRING
AS LONG AS MR. SCOTT
CAN MAINTAIN POWER.
STANDING BY, SIR.
FIRE PHASERS.
PHASER ONE FIRING.
THAT VULCAN WON'T
BE SATISFIED
TILL THESE PANELS
ARE PUDDLES OF LEAD.
PHASER TWO FIRING.
RELAY'S OUT AGAIN,
MR. SCOTT.
PHASER 4 FIRING.
ALL PHASERS FIRED, SIR.
RIG FOR SIMULTANEOUS
FIRING, MR. SULU.
COMMENCE SIMULTANEOUS
BOMBARDMENT.
MY BAIRNS.
MY POOR BAIRNS.
THE RITUAL CLOAK
IS FINISHED.
IF IT PLEASES YOU,
I WOULD LIKE TO NAME
THE JOINING DAY.
THE JOINING DAY?
I'M THE DAUGHTER
OF THE CHIEF.
TRIBAL LAW BETROTHS ME
TO OUR LEADER.
IF THERE IS ANOTHER,
I WILL STEP ASIDE.
NO, MIRAMANEE,
THERE'S NO ONE ELSE
IN MY MIND
OR MY HEART.
A GOD'S WISH
IS ABOVE TRIBAL LAW.
NAME THE JOINING DAY.
THE SOONER OUR HAPPINESS
TOGETHER BEGINS,
THE LONGER IT WILL LAST.
TOMORROW.
AND DON'T ASK FOR ANY MORE
WARP 9 SPEEDS, MR. SPOCK.
OUR STARDRIVE IS
COMPLETELY BURNED OUT.
THE ONLY THING WE HAVE LEFT
IS IMPULSE POWER.
ESTIMATED REPAIR TIME?
HANGING HERE IN SPACE?
FOREVER.
THE ONLY THING THAT'LL FIX
THESE POOR DARLIN'S
IS THE NEAREST REPAIR BASE.
I'VE ALREADY SURMISED THAT.
THANK YOU, MR. SCOTT.
WELL, SPOCK,
YOU TOOK YOUR
CALCULATED RISK
IN YOUR CALCULATED
VULCAN WAY,
AND YOU LOST.
YOU LOST FOR US,
YOU LOST FOR THAT
PLANET,
AND YOU LOST
FOR JIM.
I ACCEPT THE
RESPONSIBILITY, DOCTOR.
AND MY
RESPONSIBILITY
IS THE HEALTH
OF THIS CREW.
YOU'VE BEEN DRIVING
YOURSELF TOO HARD
AND I WANT YOU
TO GET SOME REST.
MR. CHEKOV,
RESUME HEADING 883,
MARK 4-1.
BACK TO THAT PLANET?
WITHOUT WARP SPEED,
IT'LL TAKE MONTHS, SPOCK,
EXACTLY 59.223 DAYS,
DOCTOR,
AND THAT ASTEROID
WILL BE 4 HOURS
BEHIND US
ALL THE WAY.
WELL, THEN
WHAT'S THE USE?
WE MIGHT NOT BE ABLE
TO SAVE THE CAPTAIN
EVEN IF
HE STILL IS ALIVE.
WE MIGHT NOT
BE ABLE TO SAVE
ANYTHING,
INCLUDING THIS SHIP!
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD
A WORD I'VE SAID.
ALL YOU'VE BEEN
DOING IS STARING
AT THAT BLASTED
OBELISK.
ANOTHER CALCULATED
VULCAN RISK, DOCTOR.
THIS JOINING MEANS
THE END OF DARKNESS.
IT'S A TIME FOR JOY
FOR ALL MY PEOPLE.
YOU WILL WAIT
UNTIL I WALK
THE HOLY PATH
TO THE EARTH LODGE
FIRST
TO GIVE ME TIME
TO TELL
THE PRIESTESS
THAT YOU FOLLOW
AND THAT THE JOINING
WILL TAKE PLACE.
[THINKING]
I HAVE FOUND PARADISE.
SURELY NO MAN
HAS EVER ATTAINED
SUCH HAPPINESS.
GET OUT OF MY WAY,
SALISH.
EVEN THOUGH
YOU BE A GOD, KIROK,
I CANNOT PERMIT
THIS JOINING.
NOBODY'S ASKING
FOR YOUR PERMISSION.
THEN YOU MUST
STRIKE ME DEAD.
I HAVE NO INTENTION
OF STRIKING YOU DEAD.
YOU BLEED.
YOU BLEED, KIROK.
BEHOLD,
A GOD WHO BLEEDS!
BEHOLD, A GOD WHO BLEEDS!
KILL ME.
KILL ME, KIROK,
FOR I WILL NOT REST
UNTIL I PROVE
TO MY PEOPLE
THAT YOU ARE NO GOD.
[DRUMS BEATING]
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
REPORTING TO SICK BAY.
THERE ISN'T TIME,
DOCTOR.
I MUST DECIPHER
THOSE OBELISK
SYMBOLS.
THEY'RE A HIGHLY
ADVANCED FORM
OF CIPHER WRITING.
YOU'VE BEEN TRYING
TO DO THAT
EVER SINCE WE STARTED BACK
TO THAT PLANET--58 DAYS.
I'M AWARE OF THAT,
DOCTOR.
I'M ALSO AWARE
WHEN WE ARRIVE
AT THE PLANET,
WE'LL HAVE
BARELY 4 HOURS
TO EFFECT RESCUE.
I BELIEVE THOSE
SYMBOLS ARE THE KEY.
WELL, YOU WON'T
READ THEM
BY KILLING YOURSELF.
YOU'VE HARDLY EATEN
OR SLEPT FOR WEEKS.
NOW, IF YOU DON'T LET UP,
YOU'RE GOING TO COLLAPSE.
I AM NOT HUNGRY, DOCTOR.
AND UNDER STRESS,
WE VULCANS CAN DO
WITHOUT SLEEP FOR WEEKS.
WELL, YOUR VULCAN
METABOLISM IS SO LOW
IT CAN HARDLY
BE MEASURED,
AND AS
FOR THE PRESSURE
OF THAT GREEN ICE WATER
YOU CALL BLOOD--
MY PHYSICAL CONDITION
IS NOT IMPORTANT, DOCTOR.
THAT OBELISK IS.
WELL, MY DIAGNOSIS
IS EXHAUSTION,
BROUGHT ON
FROM OVERWORK
AND GUILT.
YOU'RE BLAMING
YOURSELF FOR
CRIPPLING THIS SHIP,
JUST AS WE
BLAMED YOU.
WELL, WE WERE WRONG.
SO WERE YOU.
YOU MADE
A COMMAND DECISION.
JIM WOULD HAVE DONE
THE SAME.
MY PRESCRIPTION
IS REST. NOW.
DO I HAVE TO CALL
THE SECURITY GUARDS
TO ENFORCE IT?
[LAUGHING]
MIRAMANEE.
COME HERE.
EACH TIME
YOUR ARMS HOLD ME
IS AS JOYOUS
AS THE FIRST.
I'M HAPPY.
I'M SO HAPPY.
IF IT WEREN'T
FOR THE DREAMS, I...
MY MIND WOULD BE
COMPLETELY AT PEACE.
I THOUGHT
YOU NO LONGER
HAD THE DREAMS,
THAT YOU
NO LONGER SAW
THE STRANGE LODGE
WHICH MOVES
THROUGH THE SKY.
THEY'VE COME BACK.
THEY WERE GONE
FOR A WHILE,
BUT THEY'VE COME BACK,
AND I...
SEE FACES, TOO.
VERY DIM.
I FEEL...
I SHOULD KNOW--KNOW THEM.
MY PLACE IS WITH THEM,
NOT HERE.
I DON'T DESERVE
THIS HAPPINESS.
I HAVE A GIFT
FOR YOU.
GIFT?
WHAT?
IT MAY
MAKE YOU HAPPY.
WAIT.
[THINKING]
THESE LAST FEW WEEKS,
MY LOVE FOR MIRAMANEE
GROWS STRONGER
WITH EACH PASSING DAY.
HOWEVER, THE DREAMS RETURN
EVERY NIGHT...
FRAGMENTS OF MEMORIES.
I CAN ALMOST
GET HOLD OF THEM,
AND THEN...
I BEAR YOUR CHILD.
[LAUGHS]
YOU...
[LAUGHING]
A CANAL...
AND WITH IT, WE'LL
BRING THE WATER
FROM THE LAKE
RIGHT TO THE LODGE.
AND WE CAN EXPAND
THE SYSTEM...
SEE...
AND IRRIGATE
THE FIELDS
AND DOUBLE
THE FOOD SUPPLY.
AND WITH THE POWER
OF THE LAMP...
LAMP?
LAMP.
WHICH TURNS NIGHT
INTO DAY,
WE CAN COOK
TWICE AS MUCH FOOD,
AND AS YOU TAUGHT US...
PRE...
PRESERVE.
FAMINE.
FOR TIMES OF FAMINE.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
THAT IS WHY YOU MADE
THE LAMP, KIROK,
SO THAT I WOULD
NEVER KNOW WHEN
IT WAS NIGHT
AND I WOULD BE
FOREVER COOKING.
OH, NO. NO, NO, NO, NO.
THAT'S NOT WHY
I MADE THE LAMP AT ALL,
TO KEEP YOU
FOREVER COOKING.
[THUNDER AND WIND HOWLING]
IT'S ONLY THE WIND...
AND THE THUNDER.
I ACT LIKE
A STUPID CHILD.
I HAVE NOTHING
TO FEAR.
YOU ARE HERE.
IT IS TIME.
TIME?
TO GO TO THE TEMPLE.
THE PEOPLE WILL BE WAITING.
WHY?
TO SAVE THEM.
BUT IT'S ONLY
THE WIND.
THE WIND
CAN'T HARM THEM.
THE WIND IS ONLY
THE BEGINNING.
SOON THE SKY
WILL DARKEN,
THE LAKE WILL GO WILD,
AND THE EARTH
WILL TREMBLE.
ONLY YOU CAN SAVE US.
BUT I CAN'T
DO ANYTHING
ABOUT THE WIND
OR THE SKY.
IF WE DO NOT GO NOW,
IT WILL BE TOO LATE.
YOU MUST GO
INSIDE THE TEMPLE
AND MAKE THE BLUE FLAME
COME OUT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO GET INSIDE
THE TEMPLE.
BUT YOU ARE A GOD.
KIROK!
WHY ARE YOU NOT
AT THE TEMPLE, KIROK?
SOON THE GROUND
WILL BEGIN TO TREMBLE.
THE PEOPLE NEED
YOUR HELP.
WE'LL GO TO THE CAVES.
IT'LL BE SAFE THERE.
THE CAVES?
SURELY A LEGEND
CAN DO MORE THAN THAT
FOR HIS PEOPLE.
WHEN THE GROUND TREMBLES,
THE CAVES ARE NOT SAFE, KIROK.
IF YOU DO NOT ROUSE
THE TEMPLE SPIRIT,
WE WILL ALL DIE.
THERE IS NOTHING
YOU CANNOT DO,
MY HUSBAND.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU
WAIT FOR, GOD?
YOUR ROBES?
TAKE CARE OF MIRAMANEE,
I AM KIROK!
I HAVE COME!
I PRESCRIBED SLEEP.
YOU PRESCRIBED REST,
DOCTOR.
THE SYMBOLS
ON THE OBELISK
ARE NOT WORDS.
THEY ARE
MUSICAL NOTES.
MUSICAL NOTES?
YOU MEAN IT'S NOTHING
BUT A SONG?
IN A WAY, YES.
OTHER CULTURES,
AMONG THEM CERTAIN
VULCAN OFFSHOOTS,
USE MUSICAL NOTES
AS WORDS.
THE TONES
CORRESPOND ROUGHLY
TO AN ALPHABET.
WERE YOU ABLE
TO MAKE ANY SENSE
OF THE SYMBOLS?
YES. THE OBELISK
IS A MARKER,
JUST AS I THOUGHT.
IT WAS LEFT
BY A SUPER RACE
KNOWN AS
THE PRESERVERS.
THEY PASSED
THROUGH THE GALAXY
RESCUING
PRIMITIVE CULTURES
WHICH WERE IN DANGER
OF EXTINCTION
AND SEEDING THEM,
SO TO SPEAK,
WHERE THEY COULD
LIVE AND GROW.
I'VE ALWAYS WONDERED
WHY THERE WERE
SO MANY HUMANOIDS
SCATTERED THROUGH
THE GALAXY.
SO HAVE I. APPARENTLY,
THE PRESERVERS
ACCOUNT FOR
A NUMBER OF THEM.
THAT'S PROBABLY HOW
THE PLANET HAS SURVIVED
ALL THESE CENTURIES.
THE PRESERVERS PUT
AN ASTEROID DEFLECTOR
ON THE PLANET.
WHICH HAS NOW
BECOME DEFECTIVE
AND IS FAILING
TO OPERATE.
AND WE HAVE TO
FIND THAT DEFLECTOR
AND PUT IT BACK
INTO WORKING ORDER.
OTHERWISE...
PRECISELY, DOCTOR.
THERE'S THE FALSE ONE!
DIE! DIE! DIE!
NO! NO! DON'T HURT HIM!
MIRAMANEE!
DON'T HURT HIM!
HE CAN SAVE US!
HE'S FALSE!
I BELONG TO HIM.
THEN GO.
GO DIE WITH
YOUR FALSE GOD.
YOU'LL BE KILLED!
[SHOUTING]
KILL THEM!
WE'RE ALL DOOMED!
MURDER THE IMPOSTOR!
YOU LIED TO US!
YOU'RE NOT A GOD!
WE'LL KILL YOU NOW!
I NEED NURSE CHAPEL.
SPOCK TO ENTERPRISE.
Scott:
COME IN, MR. SPOCK.
WE'VE LOCATED THE CAPTAIN.
BEAM DOWN NURSE CHAPEL
WITH AN EMERGENCY
SURGICAL KIT.
MY WIFE...
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
WIFE?
HALLUCINATIONS?
JIM.
MIRAMANEE.
THE NURSE HAS
GIVEN YOU SOMETHING
TO EASE THE PAIN.
WHY WERE YOU
BEING STONED?
KIROK COULD NOT GET BACK
INTO THE TEMPLE.
NATURALLY,
SINCE HE DID NOT
COME FROM THERE.
I SAW HIM COME--COME.
DOES HE RECOGNIZE US?
HIS BRAIN
IS UNIMPAIRED.
EVERYTHING ELSE
IS FUNCTIONALLY
NORMALLY
EXCEPT HIS MEMORY.
CAN YOU HELP HIM?
IT'D TAKE TIME.
TIME, DR. McCOY,
IS THE ONE THING
WE DO NOT HAVE
IN ABUNDANCE.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
SPOCK HERE.
Sulu:
TRACKING REPORT, SIR.
65 MINUTES TO END
OF SAFETY MARGIN.
REPORT NOTED.
DOCTOR, IS HE STRONG ENOUGH
FOR THE VULCAN MIND FUSION?
WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
I AM SPOCK.
YOU ARE JAMES KIRK.
OUR MINDS
ARE MOVING CLOSER...
CLOSER...
CLOSER, JAMES KIRK.
CLOSER.
NO!
JAMES KIRK.
MIRAMANEE!
NO!
OUR MINDS...
ARE ONE.
I...
AM...
KIROK.
I...
AM...
KIROK.
I AM KIR--
I...
AM KIROK!
I AM...
SPOCK!
WHAT IS IT?
HIS MIND...
HE IS...
AN EXTREMELY
DYNAMIC INDIVIDUAL.
IT WORKED.
CAPTAIN, WERE YOU
INSIDE THIS STRUCTURE?
YES. WHAT'S INSIDE
IS LOADED
WITH SCIENTIFIC
EQUIPMENT.
THIS OBELISK IS ONE HUGE
DEFLECTOR MECHANISM.
IT IS IMPERATIVE
THAT WE GET INSIDE
IMMEDIATELY.
CAPTAIN, WE DO NOT HAVE
MUCH TIME.
McCOY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO GET INSIDE.
IF WE ARE NOT ABLE
TO GAIN ENTRY
AND ACTIVATE
THE DEFLECTOR
MECHANISM
WITHIN THE NEXT
50 MINUTES,
THIS ENTIRE PLANET
WILL BE DESTROYED.
THE KEY MUST BE
IN THESE SYMBOLS.
WE'VE GOT TO DECIPHER THEM.
I ALREADY HAVE
TO SOME EXTENT,
CAPTAIN.
THEY ARE
MUSICAL NOTES.
YOU MEAN ENTRY CAN BE GAINED
BY PLAYING CERTAIN NOTES
ON A MUSICAL INSTRUMENT?
THAT WOULD BE
ONE METHOD.
ANOTHER WOULD BE
A SERIES OF TONAL
QUALITIES
SPOKEN IN THEIR
PROPER SEQUENCE.
GIVE ME YOUR COMMUNICATOR.
TONAL CONTROL,
CONSONANTS AND VOWELS--
I MUST HAVE
HIT IT ACCIDENTALLY
WHEN I CONTACTED
THE SHIP.
IF YOU COULD
REMEMBER YOUR EXACT
WORDS, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
Scott:
AYE, CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, IF THE DEFLECTOR
ISN'T ACTIVATED
WITHIN 20 MINUTES,
GET OUT OF ORBIT.
GET THE ENTERPRISE
OUT OF THE DANGER ZONE.
THE LANDING PARTY
IS EXPENDABLE.
THE ENTERPRISE ISN'T.
KIRK OUT.
MIRAMANEE.
BONES, STAY WITH HER.
DO WHAT YOU CAN.
IT IS SIMILAR
TO DEFLECTOR PANELS
I'VE SEEN, CAPTAIN,
BUT FAR MORE
COMPLICATED.
CAREFUL.
I MUST HAVE HIT
SOMETHING ACCIDENTALLY.
THE BEAM CAUGHT ME,
AND THAT'S WHEN
I STOPPED REMEMBERING.
PROBABLY
A MEMORY BEAM.
YOU MUST HAVE
ACTIVATED IT
OUT OF SEQUENCE.
THERE'S MORE SYMBOLS.
CAN YOU READ THEM?
I DO HAVE
AN EXCELLENT EYE
FOR MUSICAL NOTES,
CAPTAIN.
THEY WOULD SEEM
TO INDICATE
THAT THIS SERIES
OF RELAYS
ACTIVATED
IN THEIR PROPER--
SPOCK, JUST PRESS
THE RIGHT BUTTON.
[RUMBLING]
HOW IS SHE?
SHE HAD BAD
INTERNAL INJURIES, JIM.
WILL SHE LIVE?
NO.
KIROK, IT IS TRUE.
YOU ARE SAFE.
AND SO ARE YOUR PEOPLE,
MIRAMANEE.
I KNEW YOU WOULD
SAVE THEM, MY CHIEF.
WHEN I AM BETTER...
IT WILL BE
AS IT WAS,
WILL IT...NOT?
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
WE WILL LIVE
LONG
AND HAPPY LIVES.
I WILL BEAR YOU
MANY STRONG SONS.
[GROANS]
I LOVE YOU ALWAYS.
AND I LOVE YOU,
MIRAMANEE...
ALWAYS.
EACH KISS...
IS AS THE FIRST.