CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5029.5.
RESPONDING
TO A DISTRESS CALL
FROM OUR SCIENTIFIC
COLONY ON TRIACUS.
WE ARE BEAMING DOWN
TO INVESTIGATE.
[TRICORDER PULSES]
PROFESSOR STARNES.
IT'S KIRK.
[TONE OSCILLATES]
HE'S DEAD,
CAPTAIN.
HE DIDN'T SEEM
TO KNOW ME.
CYALODIN.
SELF-INFLICTED.
[TAPE RECORDER REWINDING]
MUST DESTROY OURSELVES!
ALIEN UPON US,
THE ALIEN FROM WITHIN...
THE ENEMY!
ALL THIS...
SELF-INFLICTED.
MASS SUICIDE.
[CHILDREN'S VOICES
SHOUTING]
YOU MISSED ME.
I DID NOT.
UH-HUH.
HI.
WHO ARE YOU?
KIRK OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
I'M TOMMY STARNES.
THIS IS MARY,
STEVE, RAY, AND DON.
COME ON.
PLAY WITH US.
♪ RING AROUND THE ROSY ♪
♪ POCKETS FULL OF POSY ♪
♪ ASHES, ASHES ♪
♪ ALL FALL DOWN! ♪
HA HA HA!
♪ RING AROUND THE ROSY ♪
♪ POCKETS FULL OF POSY ♪
♪ ASHES, ASHES ♪
♪ ALL FALL DOWN! ♪
HA HA HA!
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTARY.
WE HAVE BURIED
THE MEMBERS
OF THE STARNES
EXPLORATION PARTY.
EVERYONE HAS BEEN
DEEPLY AFFECTED
BY WHAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE...
WITH SOME IMPORTANT
EXCEPTIONS.
LET'S GO AND PLAY.
COME ON!
LET'S GO!
I'M GONNA GET YOU!
[KIRK]
NO SIGN OF GRIEF.
NO, JIM, NO
INDICATION
OF ANY KIND.
OR OF FEAR.
THEY SEEM COMPLETELY
SECURE AND UNAFRAID.
AND YOU INSIST THAT
THEIR BEHAVIOR IS A
SIGN TRAUMATIC SHOCK?
I DON'T INSIST, JIM,
BUT I CAN'T DISMISS
THE POSSIBILITY.
A CHILD SUPPRESSES THE FACT
THAT BOTH PARENTS ARE DEAD?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
HUMANS DO HAVE
AN AMAZING CAPACITY
FOR BELIEVING
WHAT THEY CHOOSE
AND EXCLUDING
THAT WHICH IS PAINFUL.
NOT THESE CHILDREN,
TO THIS EXTENT.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
WHAT THOSE CHILDREN SAW
IS INCREDIBLE, JIM.
THE WAY THOSE
DEATHS OCCURRED,
ANY REACTION IS POSSIBLE
INCLUDING
LACUNAR AMNESIA.
THAT'S MY DIAGNOSIS.
UNTIL SPECIFIC TESTS
CAN BE MADE,
IT REMAINS THAT.
I'LL BE GUIDED
BY THAT OPINION, DOCTOR,
FOR THE PRESENT.
WHAT ABOUT
QUESTIONING THEM?
NOT UNTIL THE FABRIC
OF THE TRAUMATIZATION
WEAKENS,
OR YOU CAN COME UP WITH
ANOTHER EXPLANATION
FOR THEIR BEHAVIOR.
FORCING THEM TO SEE
THIS EXPERIENCE NOW
COULD CAUSE
PERMANENT DAMAGE.
ACCEPTED, DOCTOR.
CAREFUL.
I'M--I'M SORRY,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
CHILDREN.
CHILDREN,
LISTEN TO ME.
IT'S LATE AND IT'S TIME
TO GO UP TO THE SHIP.
OH, NOT YET.
BUT--BUT WE'RE JUST
BEGINNING TO HAVE FUN.
NOT NOW.
I'M SORRY.
YOU'LL GO UP
WITH THE DOCTOR.
COME ON, IT'S
TIME TO BE GOING.
WHATEVER HAPPENED HERE
IS LOCKED UP INSIDE
THOSE CHILDREN.
THE ATTACK ON
PROFESSOR STARNES'
PARTY
MUST SURELY HAVE
BEEN UNPROVOKED.
ATTACK?
MASS SUICIDE IS
WHAT IT SEEMS TO BE.
I STAND CORRECTED,
CAPTAIN.
"INDUCED" WOULD BE
A MORE PRECISE TERM.
INDUCED BY AN
OUTSIDE FORCE.
SUCH AS?
THE RELEASE OF BACTERIA.
OR A HELPLESS
MENTAL DEPRESSION
AND A STATE OF
SUICIDAL ANXIETY
COULD HAVE BEEN
CHEMICALLY INDUCED.
WHAT WOULD MAKE
THE CHILDREN IMMUNE?
I DO NOT KNOW,
BUT IT IS POSSIBLE.
THEN THE CHILDREN
WOULD HAVE BEEN EXEMPTED
BY CONSCIOUS DESIGN.
A VALID ASSUMPTION,
I WOULD SAY.
AND THEIR PRESENT BEHAVIOR
EXPLAINED BY
A FEAR OF PUNISHMENT.
OR THE PROMISE
OF REWARD.
AN ATTACK BY AN
UNKNOWN ASSAILANT...
ON AN UNINHABITED PLANET.
THIS PLANET IS
UNINHABITED, MR. SPOCK,
TO THE BEST
OF OUR INFORMATION?
AT PRESENT, YES.
[TRICORDER SIGNALS]
ODD.
GETTING A READING?
THERE SEEMS TO BE
SOME DISTURBANCE
COMING
FROM THAT CAVE.
PICKING UP
ANY LIFE FORMS,
MR. SPOCK?
DEFINITELY
NOT HUMANOID, CAPTAIN.
IMPOSSIBLE TO MAKE ANY
SPECIFIC IDENTIFICATION.
THE READINGS
DO NOT CORRELATE
WITH ANY KNOWN
INFORMATION.
OH, THAT'S STRANGE.
THAT'S...VERY STRANGE.
I'M GETTING A FEELING
OF ANXIETY IN THIS PLACE.
IT DOESN'T SOUND
VERY SCIENTIFIC,
DOES IT?
BUT IT'S STRONGEST
RIGHT HERE.
I'M NOT AWARE
OF IT, CAPTAIN.
MAYBE THAT'S
WHAT'S REGISTERING
ON YOUR TRICORDER.
I AM NOT FAMILIAR
WITH ANXIETY,
BUT I WAS NOT AWARE
THAT IT COULD
BE REGISTERED
ON SENSORS.
NO.
OF COURSE, THAT'S...
THAT'S ME.
THAT'S ME,
BUT WHAT'S
CAUSING YOUR...
TRICORDER TO REACT?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN?
YES, I'M FINE.
I'M FINE.
HUH.
JUST SOME
SYMPATHETIC VIBRATION
WITH WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
LET'S GET BACK
TO THE SHIP.
I WANT TO CHECK
OUT THOSE TAPES
FROM PROFESSOR
STARNES' TRICORDER...
AND I AM GOING
TO QUESTION
THOSE CHILDREN.
ALL RIGHT, CHILDREN.
NOW, EACH CARD IS
A DIFFERENT FLAVOR.
YOU TAKE YOUR PICK,
AND THE COMPUTER WILL MIX
YOUR FAVORITE COMBINATION.
NOW, WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
JUST CALL OUT YOUR
FAVORITES.
CHOCOLATE!
VANILLA!
CHERRY!
CHOCOLATE!
O.K.
WELL, WOULD YOU LIKE
A SURPRISE, STEVIE?
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S COCONUT AND VANILLA.
THEY'RE BOTH WHITE.
THERE, THERE NOW,
STEVIE.
THERE ARE
UNPLEASANT SURPRISES
AS WELL
AS PLEASANT ONES.
THAT WAS YOUR
UNPLEASANT SURPRISE.
NOW, WHAT
WOULD YOU LIKE
FOR YOUR
PLEASANT SURPRISE?
CHOCOLATE WOBBLE
AND PISTACHIO.
WELL, COMING RIGHT UP.
AND PEACH.
HA HA HA.
ALL RIGHT.
WHOA, IT'S GOING TO
BE A WONDERFUL
SURPRISE.
[SIGHS]
THE TESTS SHOW NO EVIDENCE
OF TENSIONS DUE TO LYING.
THEY BEHAVE AS THOUGH
NOTHING HAD GONE WRONG.
AND THEY CHECK OUT
SOUND PHYSICALLY, AND
THERE ARE NO SIGNS OF ANY
FOREIGN BIOCHEMICAL SUBSTANCE
TO ACCOUNT FOR
THEIR PRESENT STATE.
I HAVE NO ANSWERS, JIM.
THERE HAS TO BE
AN ANSWER.
WELL, CAN'T IT WAIT TILL
WE GET TO A STARBASE HOSPITAL
SO THEY CAN BE CHECKED
OUT BY CHILD SPECIALISTS?
WE'RE NOT LEAVING HERE
UNTIL WE FIND OUT WHAT
WENT ON, OR WHAT'S GOING ON.
WELL, I WON'T PREVENT
YOU QUESTIONING THEM,
BUT IT COULD HARM THE
CHILDREN IF YOU DO.
COULD BE FAR WORSE
FOR THEM IF I DON'T,
AND FOR US, TOO.
BE CAREFUL.
YEAH, THEN AFTER THIS,
WE CAN ALL PLAY GAMES.
YEAH.
[NURSE CHAPEL]
HOW DO YOU LIKE
GETTING YOUR ICE CREAM
OUT OF A COMPUTER?
MMM, THAT WAS FUN.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
YOU'RE ALL HAVING
SUCH A GOOD TIME,
I THINK I'LL JOIN YOU.
IS THAT ALL RIGHT?
PLEASE DO.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL
HAVE A DISH, TOO.
OH, OF COURSE.
A LITTLE ONE.
A VERY SMALL ONE.
IT'S BETTER THAN
TRIACUS, ISN'T IT?
THAT DIRTY
OLD PLANET?
WHAT'S SO GOOD
ABOUT THAT PLACE?
YEAH.
YOU WEREN'T
THERE VERY LONG.
YOU DON'T KNOW.
HMM, I DON'T THINK
YOUR PARENTS LIKED
IT VERY MUCH, EITHER.
YES, THEY DID.
YEAH. MINE SURE DID.
PARENTS LIKE
STUPID THINGS.
OH, I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
PARENTS LIKE CHILDREN.
HA.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU THINK.
I'M SURE YOUR
PARENTS LOVED YOU.
THAT'S WHY THEY TOOK YOU
WITH THEM TO TRIACUS--
SO THEY WOULDN'T BE
SO FAR AWAY FROM YOU
FOR SUCH A LONG TIME.
THAT WOULD MAKE
THEM VERY UNHAPPY
AND THEY'D MISS YOU.
I'M SURE THAT YOU
WOULD MISS THEM, TOO.
BIZZY. BIZZY.
BIZZY! BIZZY!
GUESS WHAT WE ARE.
I KNOW--A
SWARM OF BEES.
BIZZY! BIZZY!
WATCH OUT.
I'LL STING YOU.
NOW WAIT A MINUTE.
CAN WE HAVE SOME MORE
ICE CREAM, PLEASE?
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
IT'LL SPOIL YOUR DINNER.
SEE WHAT I TOLD YOU?
THEY ALL SAY IT.
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, CHILDREN,
YOU'VE HAD A BUSY DAY.
I THINK YOU COULD
USE SOME REST.
NURSE CHAPEL
WILL SEE YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
VERY GOOD IDEA, CAPTAIN.
COME ON.
TOMMY,
JUST A MOMENT.
I'D LIKE TO ASK
YOU A QUESTION.
COME AND SIT DOWN.
TOMMY, WILL YOU TELL ME
WHAT YOU SAW?
SAW WHERE?
IN THE CAVE,
ON THE PLANET,
ON TRIACUS.
YOU WERE THERE.
DID YOU SEE
YOUR FATHER TODAY?
I SAW HIM.
DID HE SEEM UPSET?
YEAH, HE WAS
VERY UPSET.
WHAT ABOUT?
WELL, I DIDN'T
ASK HIM.
WHAT WAS GOING ON
THAT WOULD HAVE UPSET HIM?
HOW SHOULD I KNOW?
HE WAS ALWAYS UPSET,
JUST LIKE YOU,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I'M NOT UPSET
WITH YOU, TOMMY,
OR YOUR FRIENDS.
WE INVITED YOU
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE.
WHY WOULD I DO THAT
IF I DIDN'T LIKE YOU?
YOU HAVE YOUR REASONS.
AREN'T YOU UNHAPPY
ABOUT LEAVING TRIACUS?
THAT PLACE?
THAT'S FOR ADULTS.
AREN'T YOU UPSET
ABOUT LEAVING YOUR PARENTS?
MY PARENTS?
THEY LOVE IT
DOWN THERE--
ALWAYS BUSY.
THEY'RE HAPPY.
CAN I GO NOW?
I'M TIRED,
TOO, YOU KNOW.
YES, CERTAINLY.
I'LL TAKE YOU.
I KNOW THE WAY.
KIRK TO SECURITY.
POST A GUARD
ON THE CHILDREN.
THEY'RE TO BE KEPT
UNDER CONSTANT WATCH.
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW.
CALL THE ANGEL,
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE,
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW.
CALL THE ANGEL,
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE,
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW...
YOU HAVE DONE VERY
WELL, MY FRIENDS.
YOU HAVE DONE
WHAT MUST BE DONE.
YOU HAVE COME ABOARD
THE ENTERPRISE.
NOW OUR DESTINATION
IS A FEDERATION
SETTLEMENT.
CAPTAIN KIRK
WILL UNDOUBTEDLY
CHOOSE A CLOSER STATION.
DO NOT
LET THAT DETER YOU.
MARCOS 12 HAS MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE ON IT.
NEARLY A MILLION
WILL JOIN US AS OUR FRIENDS.
THE REST
WILL BE OUR ENEMIES.
TOGETHER
WITH OUR OTHER FRIENDS
WHO WILL JOIN US,
WE WILL
DEFEAT OUR ENEMIES
AS WE DEFEATED THEM
ON TRIACUS.
A MILLION FRIENDS
ON MARCOS
WILL MAKE US INVINCIBLE.
NO ONE WILL TELL US
WHERE TO GO,
WHEN TO SLEEP,
WHERE TO EAT.
THE UNIVERSE
WILL BE MINE TO COMMAND,
YOURS TO PLAY IN.
TO ACCOMPLISH
THIS GREAT MISSION,
WE MUST FIRST
CONTROL THE ENTERPRISE.
TO CONTROL THE SHIP,
WE FIRST MUST
CONTROL THE CREW.
YOU KNOW HOW
TO DO THAT.
THAT IS YOUR NEXT TASK.
AND AS YOU BELIEVE,
SO SHALL YOU DO,
SO SHALL YOU DO.
AS YOU BELIEVE,
SO SHALL YOU DO,
SO SHALL YOU DO.
AS YOU BELIEVE,
SO SHALL YOU DO,
SO SHALL YOU DO.
MAINTAINING
STANDARD ORBIT, CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ANY REPORT FROM
THE PLANET SECURITY TEAM?
EVERYTHING
IS QUIET, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE
EXTRACTED THE
SALIENT PORTION
OF PROFESSOR STARNES'
TAPES.
GOOD.
AMONG THE TECHNICAL
FACTS HE GATHERED,
PROFESSOR STARNES
ALSO OFFERED
SOME RATHER
UNSCIENTIFIC HYPOTHESES.
LET'S SEE THEM.
LOG DATE 5025.3.
EVER SINCE OUR ARRIVAL
ON TRIACUS,
I'VE FELT A CERTAIN
GROWING FEELING
OF UNEASINESS.
AT FIRST
I ATTRIBUTED IT
TO THE USUAL
CASE OF NERVES
ASSOCIATED
WITH ANY NEW PROJECT.
HOWEVER, I'VE FOUND THAT
THE REST OF MY ASSOCIATES
ARE ALSO BOTHERED
BY THESE...ANXIETIES.
THE ONLY ONES NOT AFFECTED
ARE THE CHILDREN
WHO, BLESS THEM,
FIND THE WHOLE THING
AN EXCITING ADVENTURE.
AH, TO BE YOUNG AGAIN.
LET'S SEE SOME MORE
OF THESE UNSCIENTIFIC
HYPOTHESES, MR. SPOCK.
5032.4.
THE FEELING
OF ANXIETY
WE'VE ALL
BEEN EXPERIENCING
IS GROWING WORSE.
THERE IS ANOTHER
PORTION, CAPTAIN,
WHICH I BELIEVE YOU'LL FIND
PARTICULARLY INTERESTING.
5038.3.
PROFESSOR WILKINS FINISHED
HIS EXCAVATION TODAY.
ALTHOUGH
WHATEVER CIVILIZATION
THAT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN HERE
WAS DESTROYED BY
SOME NATURAL CATASTROPHE,
IT APPEARS ONE OF THE RACE
TOOK REFUGE IN THE CAVE.
AND, FOR OUR EFFORTS,
WE ARE BECOMING
ONLY MORE APPREHENSIVE,
AS IF
SOME UNSEEN FORCE
WERE...INFLUENCING US.
WHAT HAPPENED?
UNKNOWN.
I DIDN'T SEE YOU
COME IN, TOMMY.
CAPTAIN, AFTER WE LEAVE
HERE, CAN YOU TAKE US
TO MARCOS 12?
NO. WE'LL PROBABLY TAKE YOU
TO A FEDERATION STARBASE.
BUT I HAVE
RELATIVES
ON MARCOS 12.
I'M SORRY, TOMMY.
MARCOS 12 IS NOT
WITHIN OUR PATROL AREA.
MR. SPOCK, WE'LL PURSUE
THIS IN MY QUARTERS.
CAPTAIN, CAN I STAY
HERE AND WATCH?
I'LL BE VERY QUIET.
ALL RIGHT, TOMMY.
LIEUTENANT, HAVE DR. McCOY
REPORT TO MY QUARTERS
FOR A BRIEF CONFERENCE.
MR. LESLIE...
HI THERE.
HI.
WHAT IS THAT?
THE PLANET TRIACUS.
WILL WE SEE THAT
ALL THE TIME WE STAY HERE?
YES, WE WILL.
ALL THE TIME
WE'RE HERE.
HE SEES TRIACUS
ON THE SCREEN.
HE THINKS HE SEES IT.
MR. SULU, THE SCREEN!
WE'RE OUT OF ORBIT!
WILL WE REACH
MARCOS 12 SOON?
VERY SOON.
WHEN DID
WE CHANGE COURSE?
WE HAVEN'T
CHANGED COURSE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN, WE
HAVEN'T CHANGED COURSE?
LOOK AT YOUR
BRIDGE-CONTROL MONITOR.
WE'RE STILL
IN ORBIT, SIR.
HAVE YOU GONE
COMPLETELY BLIND?
THAT'S NOT
ORBITING POSITION.
DON'T TOUCH
THE CONTROLS, SIR.
WHAT THE DEVIL DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
WE MUST REMAIN IN
THIS ORBIT TILL THE
BRIDGE ORDERS A CHANGE.
YOU BLIND FOOL!
CAN'T YOU SEE WHAT'S
IN FRONT OF YOU?
WE'RE NOT IN ORBIT!
I WILL NOT
DISOBEY AN ORDER
FROM THE BRIDGE.
YOU ARE DISOBEYING AN
ORDER FROM THE BRIDGE.
NOW STEP ASIDE.
YOU'RE LOSING CONTROL
OF YOURSELF, SIR.
NOT YET.
I'M BEING INFLUENCED
TO DO THINGS
THAT DO NOT
MAKE SENSE.
I EVEN WENT SO
FAR AS TO CALL
STARFLEET COMMAND
TO REQUEST
A SPACESHIP
TO BE USED
AS A TRANSPORT.
IT WAS ONLY WHEN
I COULDN'T TELL THEM
WHAT I WANTED
TO TRANSPORT
THAT I BEGAN TO REALIZE
THAT MY MIND WAS
BEING DIRECTED.
I DECIDED TO SEND
A DISPATCH TO STARFLEET
WARNING THEM.
OH, GOD, FORGIVE US.
MUST DESTROY OURSELVES.
ALIEN UPON US,
THE ENEMY
FROM WITHIN...
THE ENEMY!
HE NEVER COMPLETED
THE ENTRY.
AND THE DISPATCH
WAS NEVER SENT.
EXCEPT FOR SCENES
OF FAMILY LIFE,
GAMES AND PICNICS
WITH THE CHILDREN,
THAT IS THE
COMPLETE RECORD.
WHATEVER
OVERWHELMED THEM
MUST'VE DONE SO
WITH INCREDIBLE SPEED.
OTHERWISE, THE PROFESSOR
WOULD HAVE PROVIDED DETAILS
OF THE EXPERIENCE.
HE WAS AN
EXCELLENT SCIENTIST
AND TIRELESS
IN HIS PURSUIT
OF THE TRUTH.
THAT COULD BE
WHAT DESTROYED HIM.
POSSIBLE, CAPTAIN.
EVIL DOES SEEK
TO MAINTAIN POWER
BY SUPPRESSING
THE TRUTH.
OR BY MISLEADING
THE INNOCENT.
MISLEADING THE INNOCENT?
I WONDER.
DO YOU MEAN
THE CHILDREN
MAY BE INVOLVED?
YES, DOCTOR.
SPOCK...
WHAT DO WE KNOW
ABOUT THE RACE
THAT LIVED HERE?
ACCORDING TO THE LEGEND,
TRIACUS WAS THE SEAT
OF A BAND OF MARAUDERS
WHO MADE CONSTANT WAR
THROUGHOUT THE SYSTEM
OF EPSILON INDI.
AFTER MANY CENTURIES,
THE DESTROYERS
WERE THEMSELVES DESTROYED
BY THOSE THEY
HAD PREYED UPON.
IS THAT THE
END OF IT?
NO.
LIKE SO MANY LEGENDS,
THIS ONE, TOO,
HAS A FRIGHTENING ENDING.
IT WARNS THAT THE EVIL
IS AWAITING A CATALYST
TO SET IT AGAIN
INTO MOTION
AND SEND IT MARAUDING
ACROSS THE GALAXY.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THAT THE EVIL
FOUND THE CATALYST?
I WAS SPEAKING
OF A LEGEND, CAPTAIN.
BUT MOST LEGENDS HAVE
THEIR BASIS IN FACT, SPOCK.
I THINK I
READ YOU, JIM,
BUT AS MEDICAL OFFICER,
I MUST WARN YOU
THAT UNLESS
THE NORMAL GRIEF
IS TAPPED AND RELEASED
FROM THESE CHILDREN,
YOU ARE TREADING
DANGEROUSLY.
I UNDERSTAND
YOUR DIAGNOSIS, DOCTOR,
AND I WILL RESPECT IT.
BUT NOT TO THE EXCLUSION
OF THE SAFETY OF THE
ENTERPRISE, THANK YOU.
SPOCK,
WHAT OTHER EXPEDITIONS
HAVE VISITED TRIACUS?
ACCORDING TO
FEDERATION RECORDS,
THIS IS THE FIRST.
WHAT WAS IT
PROFESSOR STARNES SAID
ABOUT THE UNSEEN FORCE?
HE SAID THAT AN UNSEEN
FORCE WAS INFLUENCING HIM,
THAT HE RECOGNIZED IT,
WAS BEGINNING
TO FIGHT IT,
AND CANCELED HIS
REQUEST FOR A SHIP.
A SHIP.
YES, A SHIP
FOR TRIACUS,
BUT WHY?
BY WHOM?
SECURITY DETACHMENT.
READY FOR RELIEF
DUTY ON TRIACUS.
ASSEMBLE IN
THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM IMMEDIATELY.
I'LL HAVE SOME QUESTIONS
FOR THAT PLANET
DETACHMENT
AS SOON AS
THEY'RE BEAMED UP.
I THINK IT'S
ABOUT TIME WE FOUND OUT
WHETHER
PROFESSOR STARNES'
ENEMY WITHIN
IS ON THE
PLANET BELOW
OR HERE ONBOARD
SHIP WITH US.
COME ON.
YOUR TOUR OF DUTY
WILL LAST ONE HOUR.
BE PREPARED WITH
YOUR COMMUNICATORS
AT ALL TIMES
TO REPORT
ANY ALIEN BEINGS.
DON'T WAIT TO INVESTIGATE.
BEAM DOWN THE GUARDS.
BEAM UP
THE SECURITY DETACHMENT
FROM TRIACUS.
SPOCK.
WHAT'S WRONG?
I AM UNABLE TO
LOCK ON TO THE PROPER
COORDINATES, CAPTAIN.
WHY NOT?
IT APPEARS
WE ARE NO LONGER
ORBITING TRIACUS.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IF WE'RE NOT
ORBITING TRIACUS,
THEN THE MEN
I BEAMED DOWN...
ARE DEAD.
CAPTAIN,
WE ARE NO LONGER
ORBITING TRIACUS.
ACTIVATE THE BRIDGE
MONITOR SCREEN.
CAPTAIN TO BRIDGE.
[KIRK]
MR. SULU, WE'RE NOT
ORBITING TRIACUS.
WITH ALL RESPECTS,
CAPTAIN, YOU'RE WRONG.
I HAVE TRIACUS
ON MY SCREEN NOW.
YOU'RE OFF COURSE.
I'M COMING RIGHT UP.
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW,
CALL THE ANGEL.
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE,
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
SULU!
FIRE AND SNOW,
CALL THE ANGEL.
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE.
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
FRIENDS...
WE HAVE REACHED
A MOMENT OF CRISIS.
THE ENEMY HAVE DISCOVERED
OUR OPERATION...
BUT THEY ARE TOO LATE.
THEY NO LONGER
CONTROL THE SHIP.
WE DO.
WE SHALL PREVAIL.
THEY WILL TAKE US
ANYPLACE WE DESIRE,
SO BACK TO YOUR STATIONS.
MAINTAIN YOUR CONTROLS.
IF RESISTANCE MOUNTS,
CALL UPON THEIR BEASTS.
THEIR BEASTS
WILL SERVE US WELL.
THE FEAR IN
EACH ONE OF THEM
IS THE BEAST
WHICH WILL CONSUME HIM.
REMEMBER HOW IT WAS
ON TRIACUS?
IF THEY RESIST,
SO SHALL IT BE
ON THE ENTERPRISE.
IF YOU NEED ME,
CALL, AND I WILL APPEAR.
OUR NEW GOAL
IS MARCOS 12.
IT IS OUR NEW BEGINNING.
WE MUST NOT FALTER.
GO TO YOUR STATIONS.
MARY, YOU REMAIN
HERE WITH ME.
HELMSMAN,
DISREGARD WHAT YOU
SEE ON THE SCREEN,
WHAT YOU THINK
YOU SEE ON THE SCREEN.
SET A COURSE
FOR STARBASE 4.
HELMSMAN,
DID YOU HEAR ME?
YES, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTACT STARBASE 4.
TELL THEM WE'RE BRINGING
THE CHILDREN THERE.
TELL STARFLEET COMMAND
I SUSPECT THEM
OF BEING ALIEN
IN NATURE,
AND I WANT A THOROUGH
INVESTIGATION MADE
UPON OUR ARRIVAL.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT...
WHAT ARE YOU
STARING AT?
I SEE MY DEATH.
A LONG DEATH.
DISEASE AND PAIN.
I SEE MY DEATH.
LIEUTENANT...
LIEUTENANT,
THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
OH, GOD!
CAPTAIN,
DON'T LET IT BE.
MR. SPOCK, YOU MAKE
THE CALL TO STARFLEET.
MR. SULU, I ORDERED
YOU TO CHANGE COURSE.
MR. SULU--
CAPTAIN, STAY AWAY
FROM THE CONTROLS!
IF YOU TOUCH THEM,
WE'LL BE DESTROYED.
MR. SULU, THERE'S
NOTHING THERE!
CAPTAIN, WHY ARE WE
BOTHERING STARFLEET?
THAT WAS AN
ORDER, SPOCK.
THIS BRIDGE IS UNDER
COMPLETE CONTROL.
COMPLETE--
THERE IS NO NEED.
TAKE A LOOK
AROUND YOU.
I CANNOT OBEY
YOUR ORDER, CAPTAIN.
TAKE MR. SULU
TO HIS QUARTERS.
HE IS RELIEVED
OF DUTY.
[GARBLED SPEECH]
FROM THE--
CONFINE THEM--
QUARTERS.
CAN'T YOU HEAR ME?
DID YOU HEAR ME?
CAPTAIN...
WE MUST GET OFF
THIS BRIDGE.
YES, WE MUST.
I'M LOSING COMMAND.
I'M LOSING
MY ABILITY TO COMMAND.
THE ENTERPRISE.
I'M LOSING COMMAND.
I'M LOSING
THE ENTERPRISE.
MY SHIP IS
SAILING ON AND ON.
I'M ALONE.
ALONE.
I'M LOSING COMMAND.
CAPTAIN.
I'VE LOST COMMAND.
I'VE LOST
THE ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
JIM.
I'VE GOT COMMAND.
CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
WHERE TO, CAPTAIN?
AUXILIARY CONTROL,
MY VULCAN FRIEND.
THIS SHIP
IS OFF COURSE.
SCOTTY.
I WANT YOU
TO OVERRIDE
THE BRIDGE
NAVIGATION SYSTEM
AND PLOT A COURSE
FOR STARBASE 4.
I CAN'T DO THAT, SIR.
WHY NOT?
THESE ARE VERY
SENSITIVE INSTRUMENTS.
I WILL NOT HAVE YOU UPSET
THEIR DELICATE BALANCE.
WE WOULD ALL BE
LOST, FOREVER LOST.
GO AWAY NOW.
GO AWAY OR
WE'LL KILL YOU.
SCOTTY, LISTEN TO ME.
THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN INVADED
BY ALIEN BEINGS.
ITS DESTINATION
IS MARCOS.
IF WE TAKE IT THERE,
MILLIONS WILL DIE,
THE WAY THEY DIED
AT TRIACUS!
OH, I'M ALL
RIGHT, SPOCK.
MY BEAST IS FINISHED.
IT WON'T RETURN.
CAPTAIN, SO LONG
AS THE CHILDREN
ARE PRESENT,
THERE IS DANGER.
THEY ARE THE CARRIERS.
SPOCK, THEY'RE NOT
THE ALIEN BEINGS.
THEY'RE CHILDREN
BEING MISLED.
THEY ARE FOLLOWERS.
WITHOUT FOLLOWERS,
EVIL CANNOT SPREAD.
THEY'RE CHILDREN.
CAPTAIN, THE
430 MEN AND WOMEN
ON BOARD THE ENTERPRISE
AND THE SHIP ITSELF
ARE ENDANGERED
BY THESE...CHILDREN.
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND
THE EVIL THAT
THEY'RE DOING.
PERHAPS THAT IS TRUE,
BUT THE EVIL
THAT IS WITHIN THEM
IS SPREADING FAST.
AND UNLESS WE CAN FIND
A WAY TO REMOVE IT...
WE'LL HAVE TO KILL THEM.
CAPTAIN KIRK--
WHAT IS IT, ENSIGN?
I HAVE BEEN INSTRUCTED
TO PLACE YOU AND
MR. SPOCK UNDER ARREST.
BY WHOSE ORDER?
STARFLEET COMMAND, SIR.
WHERE DID YOU HEAR
THIS ORDER, ENSIGN?
NOW, LISTEN TO ME.
THIS ORDER IS FALSE.
I WANT YOU AND YOUR MEN
TO RETURN TO THEIR STATIONS.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN,
BUT I MUST INSIST
YOU AND MR. SPOCK
COME WITH ME TO THE
DETENTION SECTION.
ENSIGN,
LISTEN TO ME.
DO NOT FORCE ME
TO KILL YOU, SIR.
I WILL IF I HAVE TO.
WILL YOU COME
PEACEFULLY, CAPTAIN?
ENSIGN, LISTEN TO ME.
THIS IS A FALSE ORDER, ENSIGN.
I HAVE NEVER DISOBEYED
AN ORDER, CAPTAIN.
I KNOW THAT, ENSIGN.
YOU HAVE NEVER
DISOBEYED AN ORDER,
BUT AN ALIEN BEING
IS ABOARD THIS SHIP.
I WILL NOT DISOBEY!
I CANNOT DISOBEY!
ENSIGN, LISTEN TO ME!
YOU WILL DISOBEY THIS ORDER!
STARFLEET COMMAND
SUPERSEDES YOUR ORDER, SIR!
AHH...
ENOUGH.
TAKE THESE MEN
TO DETENTION
THEN JOIN ME
ON THE BRIDGE.
THE ENTERPRISE
WILL NEVER REACH
MARCOS 12.
WE WILL NOT
BE LANDED THERE.
THE CREW WILL TAKE US.
THE CREW BELIEVES.
THE CREW...
DOES NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHEN WE MAKE THEM
UNDERSTAND AS I UNDERSTAND,
THEY WON'T TAKE
YOU TO MARCOS!
THEY WILL!
WE ARE GOING
TO MARCOS!
YOU WON'T! YOU WON'T.
WE'RE GOING TO
FOLLOW OUR FRIEND!
THEY WILL!
YOUR FRIEND...
WHERE IS YOUR FRIEND?
WHERE IS
THAT STOWAWAY?
WHY DOES HE HIDE?
HE WILL COME,
IF WE CALL HIM.
BUT WE WON'T.
WE DON'T NEED HIM.
WE'RE NOT
AFRAID OF YOU!
GOOD. GOOD, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE NOT AFRAID OF ME.
BUT YOUR LEADER...
IS AFRAID.
WHAT'S HE AFRAID OF?
HE'S NOT AFRAID
OF ANYBODY.
OF ANYTHING.
HE'S AFRAID TO BE SEEN.
AND WHEN THE CREW
SEES AND HEARS HIM,
THEY'LL UNDERSTAND THAT
HE IS NOT THEIR FRIEND,
AND THEY WON'T
FOLLOW HIM.
HE IS OUR FRIEND.
THEN LET HIM
SHOW HIMSELF.
BRING HIM OUT!
LET HIM PROVE TO ME
THAT HE IS MY FRIEND
AND I'LL FOLLOW HIM TO MARCOS 12
AND TO THE ENDS OF THE UNIVERSE!
NO!
MR. SPOCK,
PLAY BACK THE CHANT
THE CHILDREN SANG
TO SUMMON UP
THE GORGAN.
[BEEPING]
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW,
CALL THE ANGEL.
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE.
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
HAIL, HAIL,
FIRE AND SNOW,
CALL THE ANGEL.
WE WILL GO
FAR AWAY,
FOR TO SEE.
FRIENDLY ANGEL,
COME TO ME.
THE TIME HAS COME
TO SEE THE
WORLD AS IT IS.
COME ON.
WHO HAS SUMMONED ME?
I DID, GORGAN.
MY BEAST IS GONE.
IT LOST ITS POWER
IN THE LIGHT
OF REALITY.
I COMMAND AGAIN,
AND I ORDERED YOU HERE.
NO, CAPTAIN.
I COMMAND HERE.
MY FOLLOWERS ARE
STRONG AND FAITHFUL
AND OBEDIENT.
THAT'S WHY WE
TAKE WHAT IS OURS
WHEREVER WE GO.
YOU TAKE FROM THOSE
WHO DO NOT KNOW YOU.
AND WE KNOW YOU.
THEN YOU KNOW
I MUST WIN, CAPTAIN.
NOT IF WE JOIN
TOGETHER TO FIGHT YOU.
FOOLISH.
YOU WILL BE DESTROYED.
I WOULD ASK
YOU TO JOIN ME,
BUT YOU ARE GENTLE,
AND THAT IS
A GRAVE WEAKNESS.
WE ARE ALSO VERY STRONG.
AH, BUT YOUR
STRENGTH IS CANCELED
BY YOUR GENTLENESS.
YOU ARE
FULL OF GOODNESS.
SUCH AS YOU
CANNOT BE CHANGED.
YOU ARE LIKE
THE PARENTS.
YOU MUST BE ELIMINATED.
CHILDREN, I HAVE PICTURES
OF SOME OF YOU ON TRIACUS.
I'D LIKE TO
SHOW THEM TO YOU.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE THEM?
MR. SPOCK, THE PICTURES.
I FORBID IT.
WHY SHOULD YOU FEAR IT?
I FEAR NOTHING.
SO WE WERE TOLD.
MR. SPOCK, THE PICTURES.
THE CHILDREN ARE WAITING.
[LAUGHING]
THEY WOULD NOT
HELP TRANSPORT US.
THEY WERE
AGAINST US.
THEY HAD TO BE
ELIMINATED.
[BEEP]
TOMMY'S FATHER WOULD
HAVE DESTROYED YOU,
BUT HE RECOGNIZED
YOU TOO LATE.
AND YOU ARE
ALSO TOO LATE.
THE KIND ONES
ALWAYS ARE.
NOT ALWAYS, GORGAN.
NOT THIS TIME.
YOU CAN'T HIDE FROM THEM.
THEY SEE YOU
AS WE SEE YOU.
THEY KNOW WHAT YOU ARE.
EVEN THE CHILDREN LEARN.
YOU ARE MY
FUTURE GENERALS.
TOGETHER WE CAN RAISE
ARMIES OF FOLLOWERS.
GO TO YOUR POSTS!
THE FIRST
GREAT VICTORIES
ARE UPON US.
YOU WILL SEE.
WE HAVE MILLIONS
OF FRIENDS
ON MARCOS 12.
WE SHALL EXTERMINATE
ALL WHO OPPOSE US!
OUR PURITY OF PURPOSE
CANNOT BE CONTAMINATED
BY THOSE WHO DISAGREE,
WHO WILL NOT COOPERATE,
WHO DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
THEY MUST BE
ANNIHILATED.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
LOOK AT HIM.
WITHOUT YOU CHILDREN,
HE'S NOTHING.
THE EVIL REMAINS
WITHIN HIM.
I COMMAND YOU!
TO YOUR POSTS!
CARRY OUT YOUR DUTIES
OR I WILL DESTROY YOU!
YOU WILL BE SWEPT ASIDE
TO MAKE WAY
FOR THE STRONG.
LOOK HOW UGLY
HE REALLY IS.
LOOK AT HIM.
AND DON'T BE
AFRAID.
DEATH...
DEATH TO YOU ALL.
[CRYING]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THEY'RE CRYING, JIM.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW IT HAPPENED,
BUT IT'S
GOOD TO SEE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, MARY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
ISN'T IT, DOCTOR?
YES. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN
HELP THEM NOW.
MARCOS 12
DEAD AHEAD, SIR.
REVERSE COURSE,
MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
COURSE REVERSED,
CAPTAIN.
SET COURSE FOR
STARBASE 4, MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.