CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 5630.7.
WE HAVE BEEN ASSIGNED
TO CONVEY THE MEDEUSANS'
AMBASSADOR TO THE FEDERATION
BACK TO THEIR HOME PLANET.
WHILE THE THOUGHTS
OF THE MEDEUSANS
ARE THE MOST SUBLIME
IN THE GALAXY,
THEIR PHYSICAL APPEARANCE
IS EXACTLY THE OPPOSITE.
THEY HAVE EVOLVED
INTO A RACE OF BEINGS
WHO ARE FORMLESS,
SO UTTERLY HIDEOUS
THAT THE SIGHT OF A MEDEUSAN
BRINGS TOTAL MADNESS
TO ANY HUMAN WHO SEES ONE.
MR. MARVICK,
I AM JAMES KIRK,
THE CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING HERE?
YOU'LL HAVE TO LEAVE
BEFORE THE MEDEUSAN
AMBASSADOR ARRIVES.
YES. EVERYTHING
WILL BE TAKEN CARE OF.
THIS IS MR. SPOCK,
MY FIRST OFFICER.
OH, YES,
YOU'RE THE VULCAN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT
FOR YOU TO REMAIN,
BUT YOU, CAPTAIN,
AND THIS OTHER
GENTLEMAN...
MONTGOMERY SCOTT,
CHIEF ENGINEER.
CALL ME SCOTTY.
MR. SPOCK, DO YOU
HAVE THE VISOR?
YOU MUST BE SURE
TO WEAR IT.
HUMANS WHO GET
EVEN A GLIMPSE
OF MEDEUSANS
HAVE GONE INSANE.
THANK YOU, MR. MARVICK.
I SHALL BE WEARING
THE VISOR.
WE MUSTN'T KEEP
THE AMBASSADOR WAITING.
IF YOU'LL GO WITH MR. SCOTT,
I'M SURE THE TWO OF YOU
WILL HAVE A GREAT DEAL
IN COMMON.
AYE, INDEED.
IT'S A RARE PRIVILEGE
MEETING ONE OF THE DESIGNERS
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO TRANSPORTER CONTROL
CENTER ON THE PLANET.
AYE, SIR.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
INFORM THE AMBASSADOR
AND DR. JONES
WE'RE READY
TO BEAM THEM ABOARD.
KIRK OUT.
ARE YOU SURE
THIS VISOR WILL WORK?
IT HAS PROVED EFFECTIVE
FOR VULCANS.
IT'S YOUR HUMAN HALF
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
I SHALL ENDEAVOR TO
KEEP IT UNDER CONTROL.
INFORM ME WHEN TRANSPORT
IS COMPLETE.
[TRANSPORTER BEEPS]
WELCOME ABOARD,
AMBASSADOR KOLLOS.
I AM FIRST OFFICER
SPOCK.
I'M DR. JONES.
THE AMBASSADOR
IS MOST HONORED
TO MEET YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
WE ARE READY.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO ALL DECKS.
CHANNEL OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK
TO ALL SHIP'S PERSONNEL.
CLEARANCE PLANS
NOW IN EFFECT.
CLEAR PASSAGEWAYS
IMMEDIATELY.
THE AMBASSADOR
WILL BE ESCORTED
TO HIS QUARTERS AT ONCE.
DR. JONES,
MAY I CONGRATULATE YOU
ON YOUR ASSIGNMENT
WITH AMBASSADOR KOLLOS.
THANK YOU,
BUT THE ASSIGNMENT'S
NOT YET DEFINITE.
IT WILL DEPEND
UPON MY ABILITY
TO ACHIEVE
A TRUE MIND-LINK
WITH THE AMBASSADOR.
I'M SURE YOU WILL FIND IT
A FASCINATING EXPERIENCE.
I WASN'T
AWARE THAT ANYONE
HAD EVER ACHIEVED
A MIND-LINK
WITH THE MEDEUSANS.
NO ONE EVER HAS.
I WAS REFERRING
TO MIND-LINKS
I HAD ATTEMPTED
WITH MEMBERS
OF OTHER SPECIES.
I'VE HEARD,
MR. SPOCK,
THAT YOU TURNED DOWN
THE ASSIGNMENT
WITH THE AMBASSADOR.
I WAS UNABLE TO ACCEPT.
MY LIFE IS HERE.
SPOCK TO BRIDGE.
WE HAVE ARRIVED
AT THE AMBASSADOR'S
QUARTERS.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
NOTIFY ALL HANDS
TO RETURN TO STATIONS.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S TAKE
HER OUT. WARP FACTOR 2.
WARP FACTOR 2, SIR.
I WOULD APPRECIATE
AN OPPORTUNITY
TO EXCHANGE GREETINGS
WITH THE AMBASSADOR.
I AM SURE THE AMBASSADOR
WOULD BE CHARMED.
I ALMOST ENVY YOU
YOUR ASSIGNMENT.
I SEE IN YOUR MIND
THAT YOU ARE TEMPTED
TO TAKE MY PLACE.
NOT CORRECT, DOCTOR,
ALTHOUGH I AM AWARE
OF YOUR MIND ATTEMPTING
TO CONTACT MINE.
WERE YOU BORN A TELEPATH?
YES.
THAT IS WHY I HAD
TO STUDY ON VULCAN.
I UNDERSTAND.
MAY I SHOW YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS?
I THINK I'LL STAY
HERE A BIT.
AMBASSADOR KOLLOS
OFTEN FINDS
THE PROCESS OF TRANSPORT
SOMEWHAT UNSETTLING.
I UNDERSTAND.
OUR SHIP'S SURGEON
OFTEN MAKES
THE SAME COMPLAINT.
DO CALL
WHEN YOU ARE READY.
WHAT IS IT HE SEES
WHEN HE LOOKS AT YOU?
I MUST KNOW!
I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHY THEY LET YOU GO
WITH KOLLOS.
THEY, CAPTAIN?
THE MALE POPULATION
OF THE FEDERATION.
DIDN'T SOMEONE TRY
AND TALK YOU OUT OF IT?
NOW THAT YOU
ASK, YES.
WELL, I'M GLAD
THEY DIDN'T SUCCEED.
OTHERWISE,
I WOULDN'T HAVE MET YOU.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
TELL ME, DR. JONES,
WHY ISN'T IT
DANGEROUS FOR YOU
TO BE WITH KOLLOS?
SPOCK I CAN UNDERSTAND.
NOTHING MAKES
AN IMPRESSION ON HIM.
WHY, THANK YOU,
CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE VERY WELCOME,
MR. SPOCK.
BUT AS I UNDERSTAND IT,
NO HUMAN CAN LOOK
AT KOLLOS,
EVEN WITH A VISOR,
WITHOUT GOING MAD.
HOW DO YOU MANAGE?
I SPENT 4 YEARS ON VULCAN
STUDYING THEIR
MENTAL DISCIPLINE.
YOU POOR GIRL.
ON THE CONTRARY,
DOCTOR.
I WOULD SAY THAT DR. JONES
WAS INDEED FORTUNATE.
VULCAN IS NOT
MY IDEA OF FUN.
JOY CAN BE MANY
THINGS, DOCTOR.
ON VULCAN,
I LEARNED TO DO THINGS
IMPOSSIBLE TO LEARN
ANYWHERE ELSE.
TO READ MINDS?
HOW NOT TO READ THEM,
CAPTAIN.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
DR. JONES WAS BORN
A TELEPATH, CAPTAIN.
OH.
VULCAN WAS NECESSARY
TO MY SANITY.
WHAT MOST HUMANS
GENERALLY FIND IMPOSSIBLE
TO UNDERSTAND
IS THE NEED
TO SHUT OUT THE BEDLAM
OF OTHER PEOPLE'S
THOUGHTS AND EMOTIONS.
OR OF THEIR OWN THOUGHTS
AND EMOTIONS.
YOU KNOW, I WAS JUST
NOTICING YOUR VULCAN
IDIC, MR. SPOCK.
IS IT A REMINDER
THAT AS A VULCAN
YOU CAN MIND-LINK
WITH THE MEDEUSANS
FAR BETTER
THAN I COULD?
WELL, I DOUBT
THAT MR. SPOCK
WOULD DON
THE MOST REVERED
OF ALL VULCAN
SYMBOLS
MERELY TO ANNOY YOU,
DR. JONES.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I WEAR IT THIS EVENING
TO HONOR YOU, DOCTOR.
INDEED?
IT'S VERY INTERESTING.
I MIGHT EVEN SAY
FASCINATING.
BUT BACK
TO YOUR MISSION.
DOCTOR, DO YOU FEEL
ANY WAY MAY BE FOUND
TO EMPLOY
MEDEUSAN NAVIGATORS
ON STARSHIPS?
IT WOULD CERTAINLY
SOLVE MANY OF OUR
NAVIGATIONAL PROBLEMS.
WELL, THE KEY IS
THE MIND-LINK THAT
I LEARNED ON VULCAN.
AND ONCE WE HAVE LEARNED
THE TECHNIQUE OF FORMING
A CORPORATE INTELLIGENCE
WITH THE MEDEUSANS,
THE DESIGNERS--
THAT'S WHERE LARRY COMES IN--
CAN WORK
ON ADAPTING INSTRUMENTS.
I DON'T CARE HOW
BENEVOLENT THE MEDEUSANS
ARE SUPPOSED TO BE.
ISN'T IT SUICIDAL
TO DEAL WITH SOMETHING
UGLY ENOUGH
TO DRIVE MEN MAD?
WHY DO YOU DO IT?
I SEE, DR. McCOY,
THAT YOU STILL SUBSCRIBE
TO THE OUTMODED NOTION,
PROMULGATED BY YOUR
ANCIENT GREEKS,
THAT WHAT IS GOOD
MUST ALSO BE BEAUTIFUL.
AND THE REVERSE,
OF COURSE,
THAT WHAT IS BEAUTIFUL
IS AUTOMATICALLY
EXPECTED TO BE GOOD.
Kirk: YES, I THINK MOST OF
US ARE ATTRACTED BY BEAUTY
AND REPELLED BY UGLINESS--
ONE OF THE LAST
OF OUR PREJUDICES.
AT THE RISK OF
SOUNDING...PREJUDICED,
GENTLEMEN,
HERE'S TO BEAUTY.
TO MIRANDA JONES...
THE LOVELIEST HUMAN EVER
TO GRACE A STARSHIP.
McCoy: HOW CAN ONE
SO BEAUTIFUL
CONDEMN HERSELF
TO LOOK UPON UGLINESS
THE REST OF HER LIFE?
WILL WE ALLOW IT,
GENTLEMEN?
CERTAINLY NOT.
NEGATIVE.
Jones: HOW CAN ONE
SO FULL OF JOY
AND THE LOVE OF LIFE
AS YOU, DOCTOR,
CONDEMN YOURSELF
TO LOOK UPON DISEASE
AND SUFFERING
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE?
CAN WE ALLOW THAT,
GENTLEMEN?
TO WHATEVER YOU WANT
THE MOST, MIRANDA.
SOME MORE ANTARIAN
BRANDY?
WHAT IS IT?
THERE'S SOMEBODY NEARBY
THINKING OF MURDER.
IN THIS ROOM?
IT'S GONE NOW.
WHO IS IT?
CAN YOU TELL?
IT ISN'T THERE ANYMORE.
CAPTAIN, WOULD YOU MIND
IF I SAID GOOD NIGHT?
OF COURSE.
PERHAPS I'LL SEE YOU--
I WILL ESCORT YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
THANK YOU, GENTLEMEN.
BUT YOU MAKE A CHOICE
IMPOSSIBLE.
PLEASE STAY
AND ENJOY YOURSELVES.
IT WAS A DELIGHTFUL
DINNER.
SLEEP WELL...MIRANDA.
ARE YOU SURE
YOU'RE WELL ENOUGH
TO FIND YOUR WAY ALONE?
OF COURSE,
DR. McCOY.
PLEASE, DON'T
WORRY ABOUT ME.
NOW, WHERE I COME FROM,
THAT'S WHAT WE
CALL A LADY.
YES, SHE IS
SOMETHING SPECIAL.
VERY SPECIAL.
I SUGGEST YOU TREAT HER
ACCORDINGLY.
I'VE KNOWN DR. JONES
LONG ENOUGH
TO BE AWARE OF
HER REMARKABLE GIFTS.
WELL, IT'S BEEN
A LONG DAY FOR ME.
LARRY, WOULD YOU
LIKE TO STOP OFF AT
ENGINEERING WITH ME?
I HAVE A FEW THINGS
TO CHECK, AND, UH,
A BOTTLE OF
SCOTCH SAYS
THAT YOU CAN'T
HANDLE THE CONTROLS
YOU DESIGNED.
SOME OTHER TIME.
GOOD NIGHT,
GENTLEMEN.
GOOD NIGHT, SCOTTY.
YOU'RE DRESSED UP
FOR THE OCCASION, SPOCK.
VERY IMPRESSIVE.
I GENUINELY INTENDED
TO HONOR HER, CAPTAIN.
GOOD EVENING, GENTLEMEN.
GOOD EVENING.
SLEEP WELL.
BONES...
WHAT'S TROUBLING YOU
WITH THE GIRL?
WELL, SHE'S NOT
JUST ANOTHER GIRL,
CAPTAIN.
DON'T MAKE
THAT MISTAKE.
OH, I DIDN'T THINK THAT
FOR A MOMENT. WHAT ELSE?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
IT IS, EXACTLY.
SHE SEEMS
VERY VULNERABLE.
WE'RE ALL...VULNERABLE...
IN ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
OF COURSE.
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING
SO VERY DISTURBING
ABOUT HER.
MEANING
SHE'S QUITE A WOMAN.
I AGREE.
GOOD NIGHT, JIM.
GOOD NIGHT, BONES.
MIRANDA.
WHO IS IT?
LARRY.
I'VE GOT TO TALK
TO YOU.
IT'S LATE.
PLEASE, MIRANDA.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
ALL RIGHT.
COME IN, THEN.
I THOUGHT THE DINNER
WAS NEVER GOING TO END.
I RATHER ENJOYED IT.
YES, I KNOW YOU DID.
I DIDN'T.
YOU WERE
SO FAR AWAY.
I'LL BE FURTHER AWAY
THAN THAT SOON.
PLEASE DON'T
TALK OF THAT.
THERE'S SO LITTLE TIME.
PLEASE, MIRANDA,
DON'T GO WITH KOLLOS.
NOW, WE'VE BEEN OVER THIS
TIME AND TIME AGAIN.
DON'T I KNOW.
I'VE ASKED YOU
IN RESTAURANTS,
IN THE LABORATORY,
ON ONE KNEE,
ON BOTH KNEES...
MIRANDA,
HOW CAN YOU DO THIS?
LARRY, PLEASE
TRY TO UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND...
THAT YOU'RE A WOMAN
AND THAT I'M A MAN,
ONE OF YOUR OWN KIND,
AND THAT KOLLOS
WILL NEVER BE ABLE
TO GIVE YOU
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
[SIGHS]
WHY DID I EVER MEET YOU?
I'VE BEEN HONEST
WITH YOU.
I SIMPLY CANNOT LOVE YOU
THE WAY YOU WANT ME TO.
MIRANDA--
AND I'M GOING AWAY
WITH KOLLOS.
THAT'S FINAL.
I THINK YOU'D
BETTER LEAVE NOW.
SO IT'S YOU!
I DIDN'T KNOW
THAT IT WAS YOU BEFORE.
WHO IS IT YOU WANT
TO KILL, LARRY? IS IT ME?
YOU MUSTN'T KEEP THIS
TO YOURSELF.
I WANT TO HELP YOU.
SO NOW YOU WANT
TO HELP ME.
NOW I KNOW WHAT
A MERE HUMAN MALE
HAS TO DO TO GET
A REACTION OUT OF YOU--
MAKE YOU THINK
HE'S A PATIENT.
THE GREAT PSYCHOLOGIST.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY BEING
A WOMAN FOR A CHANGE?
AAH! UHH! UHH!
AAH! UHH!
AAH! UHH! AAH
MIRANDA!
WHERE'S MR. SCOTT?
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
MIRANDA!
AH, THERE, MARVICK.
SO YOU COULDN'T RESIST
THE WEE WAGER.
HAS THE AMBASSADOR
BEEN HURT?
NO HARM HAS COME
TO THE AMBASSADOR, CAPTAIN.
WHO COULD HAVE DONE
SUCH A THING?
LARRY MARVICK.
LARRY MARVICK?
WHY?
Spock:
DO YOU KNOW WHETHER
HE SAW THE MEDEUSAN?
YES, HE DID.
THEN INSANITY
WILL SURELY BE
THE RESULT, CAPTAIN.
DANGEROUS INSANITY.
THE CONTROLS
ARE ALL YOURS--
AND THE BOTTLE
OF SCOTCH
WILL BE IN YOUR
ROOM THIS EVENING,
IF YOU CAN
HANDLE 'EM.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO ALL SHIP PERSONNEL.
RED ALERT.
AN ATTEMPT WAS MADE
TO MURDER AMBASSADOR KOLLOS.
THE MURDERER IS
DANGEROUSLY INSANE.
HE IS LAWRENCE MARVICK.
BE ON THE WATCH FOR HIM.
KIRK OUT.
[CRASH]
[ALARM]
EXPLAIN,
LIEUTENANT SULU.
I DON'T BELIEVE THIS
MYSELF, CAPTAIN,
BUT WE'RE TRAVELING
AT WARP FACTOR 8.5.
AND ACCELERATING.
GET ENGINEERING,
UHURA.
THEY DON'T
ANSWER, CAPTAIN.
WARP FACTOR 9
AND ACCELERATING.
CAN'T YOU DISENGAGE
POWER FROM THERE, MR. SPOCK?
TRYING, CAPTAIN.
MR. CHEKOV,
YOUR ASSISTANCE, PLEASE.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE
ENGINEERING NOW.
PUT THEM ON INTERCOM.
Marvick: WE MUSTN'T SLEEP!
THEY COME INTO YOUR DREAMS!
THAT'S THE WORST!
THEY SUFFOCATE
IN YOUR DREAMS!
WE'RE MAKING IT
OUT OF HERE!
SECURITY
TO ENGINEERING.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
NO.
I MUST.
I CAN REACH HIS MIND.
WE'LL BE SAFE
ON THE BOUNDARIES
OF THE UNIVERSE!
WE'LL BE SAFE!
SCOTTY, WHERE ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW!
BEYOND THE BOUNDARIES
OF THE GALAXY.
WE MADE IT. WE'RE SAFE.
WE'RE SAFE,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
BONES.
OH, NO. NO!
NO, CAPTAIN.
WE MUSTN'T SLEEP.
NO! NO!
NO. THEY COME
IN YOUR DREAMS.
THAT'S THE WORST!
THEY SUFFOCATE
IN YOUR DREAMS. NO!
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
NO.
WE'LL TAKE YOU
TO A PLACE TO HIDE,
A BETTER PLACE.
NO. WE MUST STAY HERE
WITH THE CONTROLS.
COME ON, LARRY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
READY TO SPEED.
SPEED!
SPEED TO THE NEXT
GALAX--
MIRANDA. MIRANDA,
YOU'RE HERE...
WITH ME.
YES, LARRY.
I AM HERE.
I DIDN'T LOSE YOU.
OH, MY BEAUTIFUL LOVE,
I THOUGHT I'D LOST YOU.
I AM HERE, LARRY.
UH...
NO...I CAN SEE
WHAT HE SEES.
UHH...UHH...
NO, DON'T.
DON'T THINK OF IT!
LIAR!
LIAR! DECEIVER!
YOU'RE NOT ALONE!
YOU BROUGHT IT WITH YOU.
IT'S HERE. IT'S HERE!
YOU BROUGHT IT WITH YOU!
LIAR!
UHH...
DON'T LOVE HER!
SHE'LL KILL YOU
IF YOU LOVE HER!
I LOVED YOU, MIRANDA.
HE'S DEAD, JIM.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STAR DATE 5630.8.
AS A RESULT OF LARRY MARVICK'S
INSANE FEARS,
THE "ENTERPRISE" LIES DERELICT
IN UNCHARTED SPACE.
WE HAVE NO WAY TO DETERMINE
OUR POSITION
IN RELATION
TO THE GALAXY.
WE ARE IN A COMPLETELY
UNKNOWN VOID.
WHERE ARE WE?
WE ARE EVIDENTLY
FAR OUTSIDE OUR OWN GALAXY,
JUDGING FROM THE LACK OF
TRACEABLE REFERENCE POINTS.
WHEN WE EXCEEDED
WARP SPEED FACTOR 9.5,
WE APPARENTLY ENTERED
A SPACE-TIME CONTINUUM.
I HAVE THE AUTOPSY
REPORT ON MARVICK.
HEART ACTION STOPPED,
CAUSE UNKNOWN.
RESPIRATION STOPPED,
BRAIN ACTIVITY STOPPED,
CAUSE--SHALL I GO ON?
YOU MEAN
HE JUST SIMPLY DIED.
I MEAN HE EVIDENTLY
COULD NOT LIVE
WITH WHAT HE SAW.
OR WHAT HE FELT.
DAMAGE REPORT,
SCOTTY?
WE NEED
SOME REPAIRS, SIR,
BUT THE SHIP IS INTACT.
POSITION REPORT,
MR. SPOCK.
IMPOSSIBLE TO CALCULATE.
WE LACK DATA TO ANALYZE.
OUR INSTRUMENTS APPEAR
TO BE FUNCTIONING NORMALLY,
BUT WHAT THEY TELL US
MAKES NO SENSE.
OUR RECORDS ARE CLEAR
UP TO THE POINT AT WHICH
WE LEFT OUR GALAXY.
THEN WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO NAVIGATE BACK.
UNFORTUNATELY,
WE LACK REFERENCE POINTS
ON WHICH TO PLOT
A RETURN COURSE.
WE EXPERIENCED EXTREME
SENSORY DISTORTION,
AND WE SHALL DO SO AGAIN
IF WE ATTEMPT TO USE
WARP SPEED.
AND WE CANNOT RECROSS
THE BARRIER USING
SUBLIGHT SPEED.
A MADMAN
GOT US INTO THIS,
AND IT'S BEGINNING
TO LOOK AS IF ONLY
A MADMAN CAN GET US OUT.
AN ENTERTAINING
SUGGESTION, MR. CHEKOV,
BUT NOT VERY HELPFUL.
THERE IS SOMEONE
ELSE ABOARD
WHO MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP US NAVIGATE.
THE MEDEUSANS
HAVE DEVELOPED
INTERSTELLAR NAVIGATION
TO A FINE ART.
COULD KOLLOS FUNCTION
DESPITE THE SENSORY
DISTORTION?
VERY POSSIBLY.
THE MEDEUSAN SENSORY
SYSTEM IS RADICALLY
DIFFERENT FROM OURS.
PERHAPS FOR THE PURPOSE
OF THIS EMERGENCY...
I MIGHT BECOME KOLLOS.
EXPLAIN.
A FUSION--A MIND-LINK
TO CREATE A DOUBLE ENTITY.
EACH OF US WOULD
ENJOY THE KNOWLEDGE
AND SENSORY
CAPABILITIES OF BOTH.
WE WILL FUNCTION
AS ONE BEING.
HAZARDS?
IF THE LINK
IS SUCCESSFUL,
THERE WILL BE A TENDENCY
TO LOSE SEPARATE IDENTITY--
A NECESSARY RISK.
OF COURSE, DR. JONES
WILL NOT WISH
TO GIVE ME PERMISSION
TO ACCOMPLISH
THE MIND-LINK.
I DON'T THINK SHE'LL
WANT ANYONE TO INTRUDE
IN THE KIND OF RAPPORT
SHE HAS WITH KOLLOS.
DR. JONES HAS
SHOWN RELUCTANCE
EVERY TIME I'VE ASKED
TO CONVERSE WITH KOLLOS.
IN SOME WAYS, SHE IS STILL
MOST HUMAN, CAPTAIN,
PARTICULARLY IN THE DEPTH
OF HER JEALOUSY.
I COULD CONFINE HER
TO QUARTERS.
NOT SUFFICIENT.
HER TELEPATHIC POWERS
ARE FORMIDABLE.
IF IT IS AT ALL POSSIBLE,
HER MIND MUST BE SO ENGAGED
THAT NO THOUGHT OF WHAT
I AM DOING SHALL INTRUDE.
I...THINK THAT
COULD BE ARRANGED.
I MAY BE SENTIMENTAL,
BUT THIS IS
MY FAVORITE PLACE.
EARTH.
I'VE NEVER BEEN TO EARTH.
WHAT LOVELY FLOWERS.
MAY I TOUCH THEM?
CERTAINLY.
THEY HAVE NO SCENT.
TRY THESE.
OH.
OH, LET ME SEE.
IT'S JUST A THORN.
I WAS...HOPING TO MAKE YOU
FORGET ABOUT THIS TODAY.
IT DOESN'T HURT ANYMORE.
YOU MUSTN'T BLAME YOURSELF
BECAUSE MARVICK LOVED YOU.
I DIDN'T WANT HIS LOVE.
I COULDN'T RETURN IT.
BUT SOMEDAY,
YOU WILL WANT HUMAN LOVE
AND COMPANIONSHIP.
SHALL I TELL YOU WHAT
HUMAN COMPANIONSHIP
MEANS TO ME?
A STRUGGLE,
A DEFENSE AGAINST
THE EMOTIONS OF OTHERS.
AT TIMES, THE EMOTIONS
BURST IN ON ME--
HATRED, DESIRE,
ENVY, PITY.
PITY IS THE WORST
OF ALL.
I AGREE
WITH THE VULCANS.
VIOLENT EMOTION
IS A KIND OF INSANITY.
ARE YOU WILLING TO SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE
WITH THE MEDEUSANS
IN ORDER TO AVOID
HUMAN EMOTION?
PERHAPS.
A MEETING OF MINDS
IS ALL VERY WELL,
BUT WHAT ABOUT LOVE,
MIRANDA?
YOU'RE YOUNG...
ATTRACTIVE...
AND HUMAN.
SOONER OR LATER,
NO MATTER HOW BEAUTIFUL
THEIR MINDS ARE...
YOU'RE GOING TO YEARN
FOR SOMEONE WHO LOOKS
LIKE YOURSELF,
SOMEONE WHO ISN'T...
UGLY.
UGLY?
WHAT IS UGLY?
WHO IS TO SAY
WHETHER KOLLOS
IS TOO UGLY TO BEAR
OR TOO BEAUTIFUL
TO BEAR?
MIRANDA...
I MEANT NO INSULT.
PLEASE...
HERE WE ARE
AMONG THE ROSES...
A VERY ROMANTIC
SETTING.
I WISH THERE WERE
MOONLIGHT, TOO.
MOONLIGHT WOULD
SUIT YOU VERY WELL.
I SEE YOU'RE
A VERY COMPLICATED MAN.
KOLLOS, NO.
YOU MUSTN'T
LET HIM DO IT!
MIRANDA...MIRANDA, DON'T.
MIRANDA--
LET ME
GO! NO.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT A DANGEROUS THING
SPOCK IS PLANNING.
WE MUST STOP HIM!
LET ME GO!
THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS AT STAKE.
IT IS NOT POSSIBLE FOR YOU
TO BE INVOLVED.
WHY?
I'VE ALREADY COMMITTED
MYSELF TO MIND-LINK
WHEN KOLLOS AND I REACH
THE MEDEUSAN VESSEL.
WHY PUT YOURSELF
IN JEOPARDY?
THIS IS NOT A DUTY
THAT YOU CAN ASSUME.
I AM AWARE OF
THE FACT THAT YOUR
TELEPATHIC COMPETENCE
MIGHT BE SUPERIOR TO MINE,
BUT THERE IS A MORE
IMPORTANT FACTOR.
THE OBJECT IS
TO PILOT THIS SHIP.
THAT IS SOMETHING
YOU CANNOT DO.
THEN TEACH ME
TO OPERATE THE SHIP.
I CAN MEMORIZE
INSTANTLY.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
I REALIZE
THAT YOU CAN DO
ALMOST ANYTHING
A SIGHTED PERSON CAN DO,
BUT YOU CAN'T PILOT
A STARSHIP.
WHAT?
FASCINATING.
I'M SORRY, MIRANDA,
BUT YOU MUST BE REALISTIC.
YOU ARE BLIND,
AND THERE'S SOME THINGS
YOU SIMPLY CANNOT DO.
EVIDENTLY
A HIGHLY SOPHISTICATED
SENSOR WEB.
MY COMPLIMENTS TO YOU
AND TO YOUR DRESSMAKER.
Kirk: YES, OF COURSE.
IT'S THE ONLY
REASONABLE EXPLANATION.
YOU CAN'T SEE...
AND KOLLOS
CAN'T HURT YOU.
AN ELEGANT SOLUTION...
BUT I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU APPARENTLY
TRIED TO CONCEAL
YOUR BLINDNESS, DR. JONES.
I THINK I UNDERSTAND.
YOU SAID IT.
PITY IS THE WORST OF ALL.
PITY...
WHICH I HATE.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN
GATHER MORE INFORMATION
WITH YOUR EYES THAN
I CAN WITH MY SENSORS?
I COULD PLAY TENNIS
WITH YOU, CAPTAIN KIRK.
I MIGHT EVEN BEAT YOU.
I AM STANDING EXACTLY
1 METER, 4 CENTIMETERS
FROM THE DOOR.
CAN YOU JUDGE DISTANCE
THAT ACCURATELY?
I CAN EVEN TELL YOU
HOW FAST YOUR HEART
IS BEATING.
NO, THAT WON'T
BE NECESSARY.
MR. SPOCK WILL MAKE
THE MIND-LINK.
NO OTHER DECISION
IS POSSIBLE.
NO.
I WON'T LET YOU.
PLEASE.
DO NOT FIGHT US
LIKE THIS, DR. JONES.
I APPEAL TO YOU
AS A COLLEAGUE.
DO NOT OPPOSE US.
NO.
IF WE CAN'T PERSUADE YOU,
THERE IS SOMEONE WHO CAN.
YOU'LL HAVE TO TAKE THIS UP
WITH KOLLOS.
FOR YOUR OWN SAKE.
BONES, WHY HADN'T
YOU TOLD ME?
SHE WOULD HAVE
TOLD YOU HERSELF
IF SHE HAD WANTED
YOU TO KNOW.
I RESPECT HER PRIVACY.
YES. THERE'S A GREAT
DEAL TO RESPECT
ABOUT THAT LADY.
Miranda: AAH!
IT SEEMS I HAVE NO CHOICE
BUT TO OBEY YOU.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTARY.
OUR ONE CHANCE
TO RETURN TO OUR OWN GALAXY
IS DEPENDENT UPON
THE NAVIGATIONAL SKILLS
OF THE MEDEUSAN
AMBASSADOR.
WITH THAT END IN VIEW,
KOLLOS HAS BEEN
BROUGHT TO THE BRIDGE
AND PLACED BEHIND
A PROTECTIVE SHIELD.
THIS IS DELIGHTFUL.
I KNOW YOU,
ALL OF YOU.
JAMES KIRK--CAPTAIN AND
FRIEND FOR MANY YEARS.
AND LEONARD McCOY--
HA HA--ALSO OF LONG
ACQUAINTANCE.
AND UHURA...
WHOSE NAME MEANS "FREEDOM."
SHE WALKS IN BEAUTY,
LIKE THE NIGHT.
THAT'S NOT SPOCK!
ARE YOU SURPRISED
TO FIND THAT I'VE
READ BYRON, DOCTOR?
THAT'S SPOCK!
AM I ADDRESSING
THE AMBASSADOR?
IN PART.
THAT IS, PART OF US
IS KNOWN TO YOU AS KOLLOS.
AH, MIRANDA.
THERE YOU ARE.
O BRAVE NEW WORLD,
THAT HAS SUCH
CREATURES IN IT.
'TIS NEW TO THEE.
MY WORLD IS NEXT
FOR US.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I SPEAK FOR ALL OF US
YOU CALL MEDEUSANS.
I AM SORRY FOR THE TROUBLE
I'VE BROUGHT TO YOUR SHIP.
WE DON'T HOLD YOU TO BLAME
FOR WHAT HAPPENED
AND THANK YOU NOW
FOR YOUR HELP.
AND NOW,
TO THE BUSINESS AT HAND.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
CAPTAIN...
YES. MR. SULU,
RELEASE THE HELM
TO MR. SPOCK.
AYE, SIR.
COORDINATION
IS COMPLETED.
THEN GO AHEAD, MR. SPOCK.
WARP ONE
IN 6 SECONDS.
5...4...
3...2...
1...ZERO.
POSITION REPORT,
PLEASE, MR. CHEKOV.
OUR POSITION...
OUR POSITION IS SO CLOSE
TO THE POINT WHERE
WE ENTERED THE VOID,
THE DIFFERENCE ISN'T
WORTH MENTIONING.
BULL'S-EYE, MR. SPOCK.
THANK YOU,
MR. CHEKOV.
MANEUVER COMPLETED,
CAPTAIN.
TAKE OVER, MR. SULU.
THANK YOU, AMBASSADOR.
MR. CHEKOV,
PLOT A NEW COURSE.
THE NEW HEADINGS WILL BE
PLOTTED IN A MINUTE, SIR.
HOW COMPACT
YOUR BODIES ARE.
[SNIFFS]
AND WHAT A VARIETY
OF SENSES YOU HAVE.
THIS THING YOU CALL...
LANGUAGE, THOUGH...
MOST REMARKABLE.
YOU DEPEND ON IT...
FOR SO VERY MUCH.
BUT IS ANY ONE OF YOU
REALLY ITS MASTER?
BUT MOST OF ALL...
THE ALONENESS.
YOU ARE SO ALONE.
YOU LIVE OUT YOUR LIVES...
IN THIS...
SHELL OF FLESH,
SELF-CONTAINED...
SEPARATE.
HOW LONELY YOU ARE.
HOW TERRIBLY LONELY.
AMBASSADOR...
YOU MUST
DISSOLVE THE LINK.
SO SOON.
THERE MUST BE
NO DELAY.
YOU ARE A WISE CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN!
SPOCK!
DON'T LOOK!
COVER YOUR EYES!
Spock: AAH!
DON'T MOVE.
BUT, JIM!
NO ONE IS TO MOVE.
SPOCK...
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
[GASPS]
SPOCK...
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE SAFE
WITH US NOW.
HE'S HARDLY BREATHING.
HELP ME GET HIM
TO SICK BAY.
UNLESS MIRANDA CAN LOOK
DOWN INTO HIS MIND
AND TURN IT
OUTWARD TO US,
WE WILL LOSE SPOCK.
VULCAN MIND TECHNIQUES--
THEY SEEM SO UNTRUSTWORTHY
NOW THAT SPOCK'S LIFE
IS AT STAKE.
HER KNOWLEDGE OF THEM
MAY BE THE ONLY THING
THAT COULD SAVE SPOCK'S
SANITY, PERHAPS
EVEN HIS OWN LIFE.
BUT DOES SHE WANT TO?
SHE'S BEEN
IN THERE SO LONG.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE
TO BE DONE.
SHE TRIED TO HELP MARVICK.
MARVICK IS DEAD.
THAT'S DIFFERENT.
MARVICK LOVED HER.
AND SPOCK IS HER RIVAL.
IS THAT ANY BETTER?
EVEN SPOCK FELT THE VIOLENCE
OF HER JEALOUSY.
BUT THEY WEREN'T
RIVALS IN LOVE.
JIM...
YOU SHOULDN'T
GO IN THERE.
WHATEVER HAPPENS,
BONES...
DON'T INTERFERE.
WHO IS IT?
DR. McCOY?
WHO'S THERE?
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I HAVE NO NEWS
FOR YOU, CAPTAIN.
NO CHANGE?
ONLY THAT
HIS LIFE PROCESSES
ARE EBBING.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING ABOUT IT?
WHY, WHAT I CAN,
OF COURSE.
WHICH DOESN'T
SEEM TO BE MUCH.
NO DOUBT YOU THINK I CAN
WAKE HIM WITH A KISS.
IT'S WORTH A TRY,
ISN'T IT?
AFTER ALL,
HE'S NOT A MACHINE.
BUT HE IS
A VULCAN.
ONLY HALF.
THE OTHER HALF IS HUMAN.
FAR MORE HUMAN THAN YOU,
APPARENTLY.
FACE REALITY,
CAPTAIN.
HIS MIND HAS GONE
DOWN ALMOST TOO FAR
EVEN FOR ME TO REACH!
IF YOU DON'T REACH HIM
SOON, HE'LL DIE.
BUT THAT'S WHAT
YOU WANT, ISN'T IT?
THAT'S A LIE!
OH, YES, IT IS.
YOU WANT HIM TO DIE.
WHAT DID YOU DO
TO HIM ON THE BRIDGE?
DID YOU MAKE HIM FORGET
TO PUT HE VISOR
OVER HIS EYES?
YOU'RE INSANE!
YES, YOU KNOW
YOUR RIVAL, DON'T YOU?
YOU COULDN'T KEEP HIM
FROM MAKING A MIND-LINK
WITH KOLLOS,
SOMETHING THAT YOU
COULDN'T DO YOURSELF!
WITH MY WORDS,
I'LL MAKE YOU
HEAR SUCH UGLINESS
AS SPOCK SAW
WHEN HE LOOKED AT KOLLOS
WITH HIS NAKED EYES!
THE UGLINESS
IS WITHIN YOU!
THAT'S A LIE!
LIAR!
YOUR PASSION TO SEE
KOLLOS IS MADNESS!
YOU CAN NEVER SEE!
NEVER!
BUT SPOCK SAW KOLLOS,
AND FOR THAT HE MUST DIE.
SADISTIC, FILTHY LIAR!
THE SMELL OF HATRED!
THE STENCH OF JEALOUSY
PERMEATES YOU!
WHY DON'T YOU STRANGLE HIM
WHILE HE LIES THERE?
DON'T SAY ANY MORE,
PLEASE!
KOLLOS KNOWS WHAT'S
IN YOUR HEART!
YOU CAN LIE TO YOURSELF,
BUT YOU CAN'T LIE TO KOLLOS.
PLEASE GO AWAY!
WHAT DID YOU
SAY TO HER?
MAYBE TOO MUCH.
WHAT'S SHE DOING
IN THERE?
YOU MAY BE RIGHT, BONES.
MAYBE I SHOULDN'T
HAVE GONE IN.
SHE WAS BLIND,
REALLY BLIND.
REALLY IN THE DARK.
AND IF HE DIES...
IF HE DIES,
HOW DO I KNOW THAT
I DIDN'T KILL HIM?
HOW DO I KNOW
THAT SHE CAN STAND
TO HEAR THE TRUTH?
NOW, SPOCK...
THIS IS TO THE DEATH...
OR TO LIFE
FOR BOTH OF US.
SPOCK.
YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU'VE PAID A VISIT
TO THE DEVIL HIMSELF.
MIRANDA.
YOU HAVE WHAT
YOU WANTED MOST.
I AM ONE WITH KOLLOS.
WELL, I'M TRULY SORRY
THAT YOU'RE LEAVING.
GOOD-BYE.
WE COME TO THE END
OF AN EVENTFUL TRIP,
CAPTAIN.
I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D EVEN TALK TO ME.
WELL, I HAVE YOU
TO THANK FOR MY FUTURE.
YOUR WORDS
ENABLED ME TO SEE.
MIRANDA, GOOD LUCK...
HEALTH.
I HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
I SUPPOSE IT HAS THORNS.
I NEVER MET A ROSE
THAT DIDN'T.
I KNOW NOW
THE GREAT JOY YOU FELT
WHEN YOU JOINED MINDS
WITH KOLLOS.
I REJOICE
IN YOUR KNOWLEDGE
AND IN
YOUR ACHIEVEMENT.
I UNDERSTAND, MR. SPOCK.
THE GLORY OF CREATION
IS IN ITS INFINITE
DIVERSITY.
AND THE WAYS
OUR DIFFERENCES
COMBINE
TO CREATE MEANING
AND BEAUTY.
PEACE AND LONG LIFE,
SPOCK.
LIVE LONG AND PROSPER,
MIRANDA.
PEACE.