[ALARM SOUNDS]
ON MARK 8
AND CLOSING.
STEADY AS SHE GOES.
PHASER CREW,
STAND BY.
[ALARM CONTINUES]
RANGE 45,000
KILOMETERS, CAPTAIN.
FASCINATING.
RANGE 43,000
KILOMETERS AND CLOSING.
SENSOR READINGS.
A MECHANICAL DEVICE
OF UNKNOWN PROPERTIES.
I READ
NO LIFE FORMS ABOARD.
ANALYSIS,
SCIENCE OFFICER?
OBVIOUSLY, IT INTENDS
TO INTERCEPT US.
IT HAS MADE
SEVERAL COURSE CHANGES
CORRESPONDING WITH OUR OWN.
38,000
AND CLOSING.
35,000
UNCLEAR WHETHER IT
INTENDS TO ATTACK
OR MERELY COMMUNICATE
WITH US.
THANK YOU,
SCIENCE OFFICER.
COME TO 181, MARK 7.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
STAYING WITH US.
INDEED.
FULL STOP, MR. CHEKOV.
HOLD YOUR POSITION.
AYE, SIR.
[BEEPING]
ALIENS...
YOU HAVE ENCROACHED
ON THE SPACE OF THE MELKOT.
YOU WILL TURN BACK
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS IS THE ONLY WARNING
YOU WILL RECEIVE.
VULCAN, CAPTAIN.
ENGLISH.
IT WAS RUSSIAN,
SIR.
EVERY WORD.
NO, CAPTAIN.
IT WAS SWAHILI.
INTERESTING.
TELEPATHY.
UNQUESTIONABLY.
MOST IMPRESSIVE.
OUR ORDERS
ARE VERY CLEAR.
WE'RE TO ESTABLISH CONTACT
WITH THE MELKOTIANS
AT ALL COSTS.
TRUE TELEPATHS CAN BE
MOST FORMIDABLE,
CAPTAIN,
AND WE HAVE
BEEN WARNED.
WHAT PREVIOUS CONTACTS
HAVE BEEN MADE
WITH THE MELKOTIANS?
NO RECORDED
CONTACTS.
IF THEY
EVER VENTURED
INTO SPACE,
THEY EVIDENTLY
WITHDREW
IMMEDIATELY.
LIEUTENANT...
HAILING FREQUENCIES.
TIED IN, SIR.
THIS IS
CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE,
REPRESENTING THE UNITED
FEDERATION OF PLANETS.
WE HAVE CONTACTED YOUR BUOY
AND UNDERSTAND ITS MESSAGE.
WE HOPE THAT YOU WILL
UNDERSTAND THAT OUR INTENT
IS TO ESTABLISH
PEACEFUL RELATIONS WITH YOU.
LIEUTENANT, ANSWER?
NOTHING, SIR.
CLEAR ON ALL FREQUENCIES.
TRY AGAIN.
STILL NO RESPONSE, SIR.
OPINION, MR. SPOCK.
I PREFER BEING
A WELCOME GUEST,
CAPTAIN,
BUT THERE SEEMS
TO BE LITTLE CHOICE.
NONE WHATSOEVER.
MR. CHEKOV, DEFLECTORS
AT FULL INTENSITY.
INCREASE SPEED
TO ACHIEVE PLANETFALL
AS SCHEDULED.
AYE, SIR.
STANDARD ORBIT
IN FIVE MINUTES.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ADVISE DR. McCOY,
ENGINEER SCOTT
TO MEET ME
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
MR. SPOCK, MR. CHEKOV,
LET'S GO FIND OUT
WHAT IT IS
THEY'RE AFRAID OF.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4385.3.
WE HAVE TRANSPORTED DOWN
TO THE MELKOTIAN PLANET
AND HAVE ENCOUNTERED
CONDITIONS WHICH ARE
COMPLETELY CONTRARY
TO WHAT
WE WERE PREPARED FOR.
SPOCK,
WHAT IS THIS?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
SENSOR READINGS
GIVE NO INDICATION
OF FOGLIKE CONDITIONS
IN THIS AREA.
I KNEW IT HAD TO HAPPEN.
IT'S A FINE TIME
FOR THAT TRANSPORTER
MECHANISM
TO BREAK DOWN.
IMPOSSIBLE,
DR. McCOY.
MY TRANSPORTER
WAS WORKING
PERFECTLY.
THEN WHAT
ARE WE DOING HERE?
TRICORDER READINGS,
MR. SPOCK.
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
UNLIKE MR. SCOTT'S
TRANSPORTER,
THIS UNIT
IS NOT FUNCTIONING.
THEN LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
NO USE, CAPTAIN.
OBVIOUSLY
NONE OF OUR DEVICES
WILL FUNCTION.
APPARENTLY
THAT MELKOTIAN BUOY--
ALIENS.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
OUR WARNING WAS PLAIN.
YOU HAVE DISREGARDED IT.
YOU SHALL BE PUNISHED.
YOU...
CAPTAIN KIRK,
THE DISOBEDIENCE
WAS ON YOUR ORDERS.
YOURS
IS THE RESPONSIBILITY.
YOURS SHALL BE THE PATTERN
OF YOUR DEATH.
WE COME IN PEACE.
BUT WE'LL DEFEND OURSELVES
IF NECESSARY.
YOU ARE OUTSIDE.
YOU ARE DISEASE.
THE DISEASE
MUST BE DESTROYED.
YOUR PLEA HAS BEEN HEARD,
AND SENTENCE
HAS BEEN PRONOUNCED.
IT IS DONE.
FASCINATING.
WHERE ARE WE NOW,
CAPTAIN?
SPOCK, EVALUATION.
OBVIOUSLY,
THIS REPRESENTS
THE MELKOTIANS' CONCEPT
OF AN AMERICAN
FRONTIER TOWN,
CIRCA...1880.
IT'S JUST BITS
AND PIECES.
IT'S INCOMPLETE.
PERHAPS THE MELKOTIANS
HAVE INSUFFICIENT DATA
ABOUT THIS ERA.
OR PERHAPS THIS
IS ALL THEY REQUIRE
TO COMPLETE THE PATTERN
OF OUR DEATH.
AND THESE, CAPTAIN?
BEAUTIFUL SPECIMEN.
CRUDE...
BUT DANGEROUS.
WHATEVER
THE MELKOTIANS
HAVE PLANNED FOR US,
IT WON'T
BE PLEASANT.
THESE COULD
BE USEFUL.
JUST REMEMBER
ONE THING.
TO INDIVIDUALS
AT CLOSE RANGE,
THESE COULD BE
AS DEADLY
AS PHASERS.
IN THE MIDST
OF WHAT SEEMS SO UNREAL--
THE HARSH REALITY.
THIS IS NOT A DREAM.
[BANGING]
"OCTOBER 26, 188...
"1881.
TOMBSTONE, ARIZONA."
TOMBSTONE.
HELL FOR LEATHER,
RIGHT OUT
OF HISTORY.
BUT WHY HERE?
AND WHY NOW?
CAPTAIN,
THE MELKOT SAID
YOU WERE THE PATTERN.
HE LOOKED
INTO YOUR MIND
AND SELECTED
WHAT HE CONSIDERED
THE PROPER TIME
AND PLACE
FOR OUR PUNISHMENT.
BECAUSE MY ANCESTORS PIONEERED
THE AMERICAN FRONTIER.
YES.
THE VIOLENCE
OF YOUR OWN HERITAGE
IS TO BE THE PATTERN
FOR OUR EXECUTION.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH US? WE'RE TALKING
LIKE WE REALLY ARE
IN TOMBSTONE,
ARIZONA, IN 1881.
PRECISELY, IN TERMS
OF WHAT THE MELKOTS
INTEND FOR US.
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT DATE--
OCTOBER 26, 1881--
BUT WHAT WAS IT?
IKE!
FRANK! BILLY! TOM!
IKE, I WAS AFRAID
YOU WEREN'T
GOING TO MAKE IT.
LOOKS LIKE
WE DID.
I KNEW YOU
WOULDN'T LET THEM
SCARE YOU AWAY.
THEY'RE A BUNCH
OF HOT AIR,
IF YOU ASK ME.
ARE THEY REALLY?
NOW THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO FIGHT
AFTER THE WAY THEY
SHOT OFF THEIR MOUTHS.
YOU KNOW US?
[LAUGHING]
FUNNY.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT YOU, IKE.
YOU ALWAYS SEE
THE FUNNY SIDE.
I'M A BARREL
OF LAUGHS.
NOBODY CAN SAY
JOHNNY BEHAN
DOESN'T HAVE
A SENSE OF HUMOR.
JOHNNY.
HE CALLED ME IKE,
YOU FRANK,
BONES TOM...
AND BILLY.
IKE CLANTON,
TOM AND FRANK McLOWERY,
BILLY CLAIBORNE,
BILLY CLANTON.
CAPTAIN, I PRIDE MYSELF
ON MY KNOWLEDGE
OF YOUR EARTH HISTORY.
THE NAMES WERE KNOWN
IN THE ANNALS
OF THE OPENING
OF THE WESTERN SECTOR
OF AMERICA...
THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA, THAT IS.
IN THE LATE 19th CENTURY
IN ARIZONA,
TWO FACTIONS FOUGHT
FOR CONTROL
OF THE TOWN OF TOMBSTONE--
THE EARPS--MORGAN,
VIRGIL, AND WYATT,
WHO WERE THE TOWN MARSHALS,
ALONG WITH DOC HOLLIDAY.
AND THE CLANTON GANG.
ON OCTOBER 26th, THEY...
HAD IT OUT?
WHO WON?
THE CLANTONS LOST,
MR. CHEKOV.
AND WE ARE
THE CLANTONS?
WE ARE THE CLANTONS,
AND IF THIS IS
A REPLAY OF HISTORY--
HISTORY
CANNOT BE CHANGED.
[CRASH]
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
THINGS LIKE THIS
CAN'T HAPPEN.
IS THIS A DEAD MAN,
DOCTOR?
VERY DEAD, MR. SPOCK.
THAT'S ONE THING
WE CAN BE SURE OF.
DEATH IS REAL.
[PIANO PLAYS]
[CHATTER]
IKE, FRANK,
HIYA, BOYS.
I DIDN'T THINK
I'D SEE YOU AGAIN.
BILLY!
OH, BILLY!
BILLY, BABY,
I KNEW THEY COULDN'T
KEEP YOU OUT OF TOWN.
OH, YOU KNEW THAT?
COME ON.
MAYBE YOU
SHOULDN'T HAVE.
AND PASS UP
AN OPPORTUNITY
TO SEE YOU?
DON'T BE SILLY.
IT'S TAKING
CRAZY CHANCES
WITH MORGAN EARP
RIGHT IN
THE SAME ROOM.
YES, OF COURSE.
THE MAN WHO KILLS
ON SIGHT...
MORGAN EARP.
CAPTAIN, SINCE
WE HAVE SEEN THAT DEATH
IS THE ONE REALITY
IN THIS SITUATION,
I SERIOUSLY SUGGEST
YOU RESEAT YOURSELF
IMMEDIATELY...
WITHOUT MOVING A MUSCLE
OF EITHER HAND.
IF I REMEMBER CORRECTLY,
THAT WOULD INVOLVE YOU
IN WHAT WAS CALLED,
THE FAST DRAW.
IT INITIATED
UNFORTUNATE EVENTS.
YOU BOYS WANT
YOUR USUAL?
ABSOLUTELY. A HALF
A GALLON OF SCOTCH.
YOU KNOW WE AIN'T GOT
NOTHIN' BUT BOURBON,
UNLESS YOU WANT
CORN WHISKEY.
I WISH IT WAS
ALL OVER.
IKE, I SAW VIRGIL
OUT PATROLLING
THIS MORNING.
GOOD OLD VIRGIL.
WE CAN ALWAYS
COUNT ON HIM.
THEY BEEN
BLOWING OFF
ALL OVER TOWN
HOW THEY CHASED
THE CLANTONS OUT.
YOU'LL SHOW 'EM NOW,
WON'T YOU?
I DON'T THINK
WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE ANY CHOICE.
YOU'LL DIRTY YOURSELF
WITH THIS SCUM. COME ON.
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF HER.
NOW, CLAIBORNE--
NOW, NOW, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, WE DON'T WANT
ANY TROUBLE.
IF YOU DON'T WANT ANY TROUBLE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN MY TOWN?
JUST LEAVE US ALONE,
MR. EARP.
THAT'S ALL WE ASK.
FIVE OF YOU. YOU'D LIKE
ME TO DRAW, WOULDN'T YOU?
ALL RIGHT, I WILL...
SOON ENOUGH.
I BELIEVE HE WAS
ACTUALLY TRYING
TO PROVOKE A DISPUTE
WITH MR. CHEKOV.
CLOSE, IKE. LUCKY
THERE WASN'T TWO OF THEM.
I GUESS SO.
SYLVIA'S RIGHT.
THEY'VE BEEN BAD-MOUTHING
SOMETHING FIERCE
ALL OVER TOWN.
YOU BOYS WATCH IT.
I ASSURE YOU, SIR,
WE SHALL WATCH IT...
AND EVERYTHING
EXTREMELY CLOSELY.
BILLY,
YOU WERE WONDERFUL.
UM, MR. CHEKOV...
WHAT CAN I DO, CAPTAIN?
YOU KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS
SUPPOSED TO MAINTAIN
GOOD RELATIONS
WITH THE NATIVES.
YOUNG LADY...
YES, IKE?
I'D LIKE TO TALK
TO MR.--TO BILLY ALONE,
IF YOU DON'T MIND.
ALL RIGHT.
I UNDERSTAND.
BILLY CLAIBORNE,
YOU BE CAREFUL.
MR. CHEKOV,
MR. SPOCK...
EXCEPT FOR
OUR HANDGUNS,
WE HAVEN'T CHANGED,
NOT EVEN OUR CLOTHING,
YET THESE PEOPLE
SEE AND HEAR US
AS THE CLANTONS.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S SUCH
A BAD THING, CAPTAIN.
THE DAY IS STILL YOUNG,
ENSIGN.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT HAVE WE GOT?
WE'RE HERE
IN TOMBSTONE, ARIZONA,
OCTOBER 26, 1881--
THE DAY OF THE GUNFIGHT
AT O.K. CORRAL--
AND WE'RE THE CLANTONS,
AND MORGAN EARP
HAS JUST GONE OFF
TO TELL HIS BROTHERS
THAT WE'RE HERE.
AND IF THIS IS INDEED
SOME SORT OF A REPLAY
OF HISTORY,
THE EARPS WILL KILL
THE CLANTONS
AT THE O.K. CORRAL
AT 5:00 THIS AFTERNOON.
WELL, WE'RE NOT GOING
TO BE AT THE O.K. CORRAL
AT 5:00 THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU, BARTENDER...ED.
YOU, UH, YOU CLAIM
YOU KNOW US.
I AIN'T MAKING NO BIG
CLAIMS ABOUT YOU
TO NOBODY.
JUST SO HAPPENS.
TAKE A CLOSE LOOK AT ME.
YEAH?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM?
IKE CLANTON. WHO DO YOU
THINK YOU ARE?
WELL, I KNOW THIS IS HARD
TO UNDERSTAND,
BUT I'M CAPTAIN
JAMES T. KIRK
OF THE SPACESHIP
ENTERPRISE.
THESE MEN
ARE PART OF MY CREW.
WE'RE NOT REALLY HERE.
WE'RE FROM THE FUTURE.
[LAUGHING]
WE HAVEN'T BEEN BORN YET.
[LAUGHING LOUDER]
FEEL THE MATERIAL
IN MY SHIRT.
NOW FEEL THE MATERIAL
IN YOUR OWN SHIRT.
DO YOU NOTICE
ANY DIFFERENCE?
NO.
DO THESE CLOTHES
LOOK LIKE YOURS?
NOT EXACTLY.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN CLOTHES
LIKE THIS BEFORE?
SURE.
WHERE?
ON THE CLANTONS.
[LAUGHING]
YOU CLANTONS ARE ALWAYS
GREAT WITH THE JOKES.
THAT'S WHY WE LIKE YOU.
I'M NOT JOKING.
ONLY DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN YOU
AND THE EARPS
IS THAT THEY NEVER JOKE.
I'M NOT JOKING!
I'M NOT IKE CLANTON!
IT'S OK WITH ME, IKE.
ANYTHING YOU SAY.
DON'T MAKE NO DIFFERENCE
WHO I THINK YOU ARE.
YOUR PROBLEM IS,
WHO DOES WYATT EARP
THINK YOU ARE?
[LAUGHING]
GOOD MORNING, GENTLEMEN.
MY NAME IS JAMES KIRK,
AND I'M AFRAID THERE'S
BEEN SOME SORT OF
MISUNDERSTANDING.
CLANTON, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TRYING TO PULL,
BUT WE WARNED YOU
NOT TO SHOW YOUR UGLY
FACE IN TOWN AGAIN.
YES, OF COURSE YOU DID,
AND I WANTED TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT THAT.
WE'RE DONE
TALKING, CLANTON.
THERE'S BEEN SOME
SORT OF MISTAKE,
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
ALL RIGHT, CLANTON.
ONE MORE CHANCE--YOUR LAST.
YOU'VE GOT
UNTIL 5:00 TONIGHT
TO GET YOUR HORSE-STEALING
SCURVY CREW OUT OF TOWN.
ALL THE WAY.
YES, WE'D BE GLAD TO.
WE DON'T WANT TO FIGHT.
I ALWAYS SAID
YOU WAS YELLOW,
CLANTON.
I'LL MAKE ONE MORE
ATTEMPT TO GET THROUGH
TO YOU, MR. EARP.
MY NAME IS NOT CLANTON,
IT'S KIRK.
OH, YEAH. WE HEARD
THE TALK ABOUT
YOUR JOKES.
I'M NOT JOKING.
SURE. WELL, I'M GLAD
TO MEET YOU...
MR. KIRK.
DRAW, CLANTON.
NOT ME, MR. EARP.
YOU DRAW, OR I WILL.
NO, WYATT.
LET ME.
WHEN THE TIME COMES,
I'LL PAY HIM
FOR THIS.
WE DON'T WANT
ANY TROUBLE.
WE'D BE GLAD
TO COOPERATE.
5:00, CLANTON.
IS THAT CLEAR?
IF YOU'RE IN TOWN
AT 5:01,
WE'LL KILL
EVERY ONE OF YOU
WHETHER YOU DRAW OR NOT.
IS THAT CLEAR?
OUCH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT DO YOU CALL
THAT STUFF--FIRE?
TAOS LIGHTNING.
STRAIGHT BOURBON.
TRY SOME.
IN SMALL AMOUNTS,
IT WAS CONSIDERED
MEDICINAL.
THEY OUGHT TO LABEL IT
"FOR EXTERNAL USE ONLY."
IT JUST TAKES A BIT OF
GETTING USED TO, CAPTAIN.
ACTUALLY, A MAN
COULD GROW QUITE FOND
OF THIS STUFF.
TAKE IT EASY,
MR. SCOTT.
I HATE TO THINK WHAT
THAT STUFF'S DOING
TO YOUR
STOMACH LINING.
AND YOUR REFLEXES.
AND WE'RE GONNA NEED
FAST REFLEXES FROM NOW ON.
THERE'S NO NEGOTIATING
WITH THE EARPS.
WE KNOW THAT.
AYE. IF WE ONLY
HAD A PHASER.
OR A COMMUNICATOR.
IT'D BE A PLEASURE
TO WATCH THOSE EARPS
AS WE BEAMED
BACK TO THE SHIP
AT EXACTLY 4:59:30.
COULD WE MAKE
A COMMUNICATOR?
IMPOSSIBLE, CAPTAIN.
IN THIS CENTURY,
THERE ARE NO METAL ALLOYS
OR POWER SOURCES
TO MAKE DEVICES
SUCH AS OURS.
THE PROBLEM IS CLEAR, SPOCK.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO SEEK
CONTEMPORARY SOLUTIONS.
WHERE'S CHEKOV?
MR. CHEKOV IS INVOLVED,
CAPTAIN.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE COME
BACK TO TOWN, BILLY.
MORGAN WILL KILL YOU
BECAUSE HE WANTS ME.
WITH HIS OUTDATED WEAPON?
IF HE SHOOTS AT ME,
I WILL JUST...
STEP OUT OF THE WAY.
YOU CAN JOKE ABOUT IT.
I'VE SEEN 'EM IN ACTION.
ESPECIALLY MORGAN.
A LOT OF PEOPLE AND THINGS
HAVE TRIED TO KILL ME.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
MR. CHEKOV--
I MEAN BILLY...
COME ALONG.
YES, SIR.
BILLY?
PLEASE, DON'T EVEN
GO NEAR HIM.
GENTLEMEN.
WHERE ARE WE GOING,
CAPTAIN?
TO EXERCISE
THE BETTER PART OF VALOR.
WELL, THAT SETTLES THAT.
A FORCE FIELD.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
IT IS OBVIOUS
THE MELKOTIANS
ARE NOT GOING
TO PERMIT US
TO LEAVE THIS TOWN.
IF WE COULD ONLY
CONTACT THE ENTERPRISE.
YES, BUT WHERE IS
THE ENTERPRISE?
MR. CHEKOV, IF YOU WERE
IN CHARGE OF THE ENTERPRISE,
WHAT WOULD YOU
BE DOING?
I'D BE USING
THE SHIP'S SENSORS
TRYING TO LOCATE US.
VERY GOOD. IF WE
COULD FIND THE PLACE
WHERE WE BEAMED DOWN,
THE SHIP MIGHT
LOCK IN AND BEAM US UP.
WELL, LET'S GET THERE.
THERE'S NO WAY WE CAN
KNOW WHERE IT IS, DOCTOR.
IT COULD BE ANYWHERE
WITHIN A 1,000-MILE RADIUS.
MR. SPOCK, WHY DON'T YOU
JOIN US COMMON HUMANOIDS
IN TRYING TO FIND
A WAY OUT OF HERE
AND QUIT EXPLAINING
WHY WE CAN'T GET OUT
OF HERE.
WE HAVE UNTIL 5:00
TO FIND THAT WAY.
NOW CONSIDER THIS--
WHAT MATERIALS
WERE ON HAND IN 1881
THAT COULD HELP US
FIGHT THE EARPS
ON THEIR OWN TERMS?
WE HAVE THESE,
CAPTAIN.
NO, THE MELKOTS GAVE US
THOSE TO EXECUTE US.
WE HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO PUT THE EARPS
OUT OF ACTION.
IS THERE ANYTHING
THAT EXISTS HERE AND NOW
THAT COULD HELP US
OUT OF THIS TRAP?
ALL THOSE
WESTERN COSSACKS HAD
WERE POISONOUS SNAKES
AND CACTUS PLANTS.
BONES...THE VENOM.
THE PLANTS.
CAN YOU MAKE
USE OF THEM?
A TRANQUILIZER!
OF COURSE, JIM. I CAN
MAKE A TRANQUILIZER!
I COULD MAKE A DEVICE
TO DELIVER IT ON TARGET.
FIRST, BONES,
THE INGREDIENTS
YOU REQUIRE?
I KNOW THE PLACE TO GET
THE PROPER DRUGS.
I'LL NEED A MORTAR
AND A PESTLE.
CHEKOV,
MORTAR AND PESTLE.
HOW DO YOU
INTEND TO DELIVER
THE TRANQUILIZER
ON TARGET?
I SHALL NEED SOME FUSING
AND SOME COTTON WADDING.
COTTON WADDING--
TRY THE APOTHECARY.
AYE.
I SHALL MANUFACTURE
THE EQUIVALENT
OF AN ANCIENT
GENERATING CANISTER,
MORE FAMILIARLY KNOWN
AS A GAS GRENADE.
I'LL BE ABOUT
FIVE MINUTES YET.
YOU COULD COME BACK.
WELL, THANK YOU.
MIND IF I LOOK
AROUND A BIT?
CRUDE,
BUT VERY USABLE.
I WOULDN'T
TOUCH THAT STUFF
IF I WAS YOU.
OH, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY.
I KNOW HOW
TO HANDLE THIS.
I HAVE
AN URGENT NEED
FOR A SMALL SUPPLY
OF THIS DRUG, TOO.
THAT STUFF AIN'T MINE.
IT BELONGS TO HIM.
YOU'D BETTER ASK HIM.
OH, SO YOU'RE
THE DENTIST.
WELL, I'M A PHYSICIAN,
AND I HAVE A SERIOUS
EMERGENCY.
I WONDER IF YOU'D MIND
IF I BORROW
A SMALL QUANTITY
OF THIS.
YOU WANT IT NOW?
MY NAME IS McCOY.
I'M A DOCTOR.
THAT JOKE IS ALL
AROUND TOWN ALREADY...
McLOWERY.
WELL, MY NAME
IS STILL HOLLIDAY.
DOC HOLLIDAY.
THE EMERGENCY IS REAL.
I NEED THESE THINGS.
YOUR EMERGENCY
SURE IS REAL.
GO ON, TAKE THE STUFF.
HAVE SOME MORE FUN.
HA HA. TAKE MY BAG.
ONLY, BEST YOU BE
FINISHED BEFORE 5:00.
THAT IS MY INTENTION,
DOCTOR.
BECAUSE AT ONE MINUTE
PAST 5:00,
YOU'LL FIND A HOLE
IN YOUR HEAD...
RIGHT FROM THIS GUN.
AHEM.
SYLVIA!
HELLO.
BILLY CLAIBORNE,
DO YOU KNOW HOW CRAZY
I AM ABOUT YOU?
THAT'S...VERY NICE.
WELL, AREN'T YOU
GOING TO ASK ME
WHAT I'VE GOT
IN MY SHOPPING BAG?
THAT'S...JUST WHAT I WAS
PREPARING TO INQUIRE.
HAVE YOU BEEN SHOPPING?
OF COURSE, SILLY!
WHAT ELSE
WOULD I BE DOING
ON A BEAUTIFUL AFTERNOON
WITH THE DANCE
ONLY ONE WEEK AWAY?
OR HAVE YOU
FORGOTTEN THAT ALREADY?
NO...NO,
I HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN.
I AM LOOKING
FORWARD TO IT...
MOST EAGERLY.
YOU WILL BE
ABSOLUTELY WILD
WHEN YOU SEE ME
IN THE NEW GOWN
I'M GOING TO MAKE.
I FOUND THIS MOST
SCRUMPTIOUS MATERIAL,
YARDS AND YARDS OF IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I WAS THINKING, BILLY?
I WAS THINKING
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL
WEDDING GOWN
IT WOULD MAKE.
WHY DON'T WE
JUST TURN THAT DANCE
INTO A WEDDING BALL?
IT WOULD BE SO HEAVENLY.
MARRIED?
I'M...AFRAID...
THAT WOULDN'T
BE POSSIBLE.
BUT I'M POSITIVE
THE GOWN WILL BE READY.
AND WHAT ELSE IS THERE
TO STOP A WEDDING?
BUT IT IS
ABSOLUTELY IMPOSSIBLE.
I AM NOT SOMEONE
YOU CAN MARRY.
IF...ONLY I COULD
MAKE...CLEAR TO YOU...
WHAT I REALLY AM.
DO YOU THINK
I DON'T KNOW?
BILLY CLAIBORNE...
YOU ARE A CATTLE RUSTLER
AND A HORSE THIEF...
AND I DON'T CARE
WHAT ELSE.
I WARNED YOU, CLAIBORNE.
STAY AWAY.
AAH!
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO TAKE ANYTHING
FROM THAT SCUM,
NOT WHILE I'M HERE.
MR. EARP.
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF HER.
AAH!
BILLY!
THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN DO, JIM.
COME ON, CLANTON.
LET'S DO IT NOW.
CAPTAIN, LET ME.
NO!
YEAH, COME ON,
CAPTAIN.
LET HIM.
CAPTAIN, WE CAN'T
JUST STAND HERE AND TAKE IT!
YES, WE CAN.
BUT THEY MURDERED CHEKOV!
IF YOU THINK I'M GOING TO--
SCOTTY...
THEY'RE TRYING TO PUSH US
INTO SOMETHING
WE'RE NOT READY FOR.
AND IT IS NOT
YET OUR TIME.
LET IT GO, JIM.
HE'S DEAD.
MAYBE HE WOULDN'T BE
IF I HADN'T IGNORED
THE MELKOT WARNING.
WE ALL KNEW THE RISK
WHEN WE JOINED THE SERVICE.
NOW LET IT GO.
GENTLEMEN,
THERE IS ONE THING
WHICH REQUIRES
THE IMMEDIATE ATTENTION
OF ALL OF US--
SPECIFICALLY, OUR FUTURE.
BUT NOT THIS MINUTE,
SPOCK.
IT TAKES US...
A LITTLE LONGER.
I UNDERSTAND
THE FEELING, CAPTAIN.
YOU TALK ABOUT
ANOTHER MAN'S FEELINGS.
WHAT DO YOU FEEL, SPOCK?
MY FEELINGS ARE NOT SUBJECT
FOR DISCUSSION, DOCTOR.
BECAUSE THERE ARE
NO FEELINGS TO DISCUSS!
MR. SPOCK,
CHEKOV IS DEAD!
I SAY IT NOW
AND I CAN HARDLY
BELIEVE IT,
BUT YOU WORKED
CLOSELY WITH HIM.
THAT DESERVES
SOME MEMORIAL.
SPOCK WILL HAVE NO TRUCK
WITH GRIEF, SCOTTY.
IT'S HUMAN.
BONES...SCOTTY--
CAPTAIN...
IT'S QUITE ALL RIGHT.
THEY FORGET I AM
HALF HUMAN.
[CLOCK CHIMES THE HOUR]
WE DON'T HAVE
MUCH TIME.
CAPTAIN...I VAGUELY REMEMBER
THE HISTORICAL ACCOUNT
OF THE FAMOUS BATTLE
IN WHICH WE ARE ABOUT
TO ENGAGE,
BUT I AM CONFUSED.
ABOUT WHAT?
SINCE EACH OF US
REPRESENTS MEMBERS
OF THE CLANTON GANG--
YOU, IKE CLANTON,
I, FRANK McLOWERY--
THEN MR. CHEKOV WOULD
BE THE OTHER BILLY,
WOULD HE NOT?
WILLIAM CLAIBORNE,
THAT'S RIGHT.
BUT DID NOT
WILLIAM CLAIBORNE
SURVIVE THE BATTLE
AT THE O.K. CORRAL?
GET TO THE POINT, SPOCK.
MR. CHEKOV IS DEAD.
BUT IN THE ACTUAL GUNFIGHT,
WILLIAM CLAIBORNE SURVIVED.
YES.
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT MEANS IT
DOESN'T HAVE TO HAPPEN
THE WAY IT HAPPENED.
WE CAN CHANGE IT.
BONES, HOW'S
THE TRANQUILIZER COMING?
I'LL HAVE IT READY
BEFORE SPOCK.
ANOTHER HOUR.
SPOCK?
AND WE'LL HAVE
A TRANQUILIZER GRENADE?
NOT PRECISELY.
FORGET PRECISION.
WILL IT WORK?
IT SHOULD.
MAKE SURE IT DOES, SPOCK.
IF WE DON'T
TRANQUILIZE THEM,
WE'LL HAVE TO FIGHT THEM.
AND IF WE FIGHT THEM,
WE ALL DIE.
WE KNOW THAT.
NEGOTIATING WITH THEM
COULD BUY US MORE TIME,
CAPTAIN.
BUT NOT WITH THE EARPS.
I'VE TRIED THAT. THAT'S OUT.
THERE MUST BE A WAY.
HISTORY HAS BEEN CHANGED
IN THE FACT THAT
BILLY CLAIBORNE DIDN'T DIE,
BUT CHEKOV
IS LYING THERE DEAD.
THAT MEANS THERE MUST BE
A WAY TO CHANGE THIS TIME
IN HISTORY.
IT WOULD BE WORTH A TRY,
AT LEAST UNTIL WE'RE CERTAIN
OF THE DEVICE.
THEN PERHAPS WE COULD
QUIET THINGS DOWN.
BUT NOT WITH THE EARPS.
THERE IS...
ONE OTHER PLACE I CAN TRY.
YOU LOOKING
FOR SOMEBODY?
YES, SHERIFF.
I WANT YOU
TO STOP THE FIGHT.
STOP IT?
WHO WANTS TO STOP IT?
I SURE DON'T. YOU DON'T.
YOU DIDN'T YESTERDAY.
I DO NOW.
SINCE WHEN DOES
A CLANTON RUN CRAWLING
TO THE LAW FOR HELP?
HOW ELSE IS HE
GONNA GET JUSTICE?
FROM THIS! YOU AND YOUR BOYS
SET UP THIS WHOLE THING
TO TAKE CARE OF THE EARPS.
IT'S A LITTLE LATE
TO DECIDE YOU DON'T HAVE
THE BELLY FOR IT.
IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
SHERIFF! SHERIFF...
THERE MUST BE PLENTY
OF DECENT PEOPLE
IN THIS TOWN
WHO DON'T LIKE
THE EARPS.
LET'S ORGANIZE THEM.
DON'T TALK NONSENSE.
PEOPLE IN THIS TOWN
ARE COUNTING ON YOU
TO GET RID OF
THE EARPS FOR THEM.
THEN THE PEOPLE
BETTER WAKE UP
AND LET THE LAW
WORK FOR THEM.
YOU CAN TALK THAT WAY
AFTER WHAT THE EARPS
DID TO BILLY TODAY?
NOBODY HERE WILL DENY YOU
YOUR RIGHT TO YOUR REVENGE.
YES, I WANT REVENGE.
I WANT TO...
CRUSH THE LIFE
OUT OF THE EARPS.
BUT I CAN'T JUST
KILL THEM.
LISTEN TO ME.
GET DOWN TO THE O.K. CORRAL,
KEEP OUT OF SIGHT.
WHEN THE EARPS
COME LOOKING...
YOU BUSHWHACK 'EM!
CAN'T I GET IT THROUGH
YOUR STUPID HEAD
I CAN'T JUST KILL THEM?!
I CAN'T JUST KILL 'EM!
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
I CAN'T MURDER THEM!
I CAN'T KILL THEM!
KILL 'EM ANY WAY
YOU CAN!
THERE'LL BE NO QUESTIONS
ASKED. HONEST.
I GUARANTEE THAT!
THESE CRUDE SUPPLIES
WE WERE FORCED TO USE
WORKED QUITE WELL.
I DOUBT THAT THIS
COMBINATION OF THINGS
WAS EVER USED
FOR ANY PURPOSE
QUITE LIKE THIS.
PERHAPS THEY WOULD'VE BEEN
IF THEY'D HAD YOUR
INGENUITY, DOCTOR.
CAPTAIN.
HOW SOON WILL
THAT BE READY?
RIGHT NOW.
GOOD. HOW LONG
WILL IT TAKE
THE TRANQUILIZER
TO HAVE EFFECT?
3 OR 4 SECONDS.
HOW DID YOU MANAGE
TO TEST IT?
IT HAS NOT BEEN TESTED.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
NOTHING CAN GO WRONG.
UP TO NOW,
EVERYTHING HAS GONE WRONG.
I WANT IT TESTED NOW.
WOULD A VOLUNTEER
SOLVE THE PROBLEM?
IT WOULD.
ALL RIGHT.
ON ONE CONDITION.
THAT I'M WIDE AWAKE
AND WITH YOU
AT 5:00.
GUARANTEED.
AYE.
IT'S TO KILL THE PAIN.
BUT THIS IS PAINLESS.
WELL, YOU SHOULD'VE WARNED
ME SOONER, MR. SPOCK.
FIRE AWAY.
IT SHOULD HAVE WORKED.
DID YOU INHALE
THE GAS, SCOTTY?
AYE. DEEPLY.
YOU STILL FEEL
ALL RIGHT?
I NEVER FELT
BETTER.
NO DIZZINESS?
NO SWEATING?
NO PALPITATIONS?
IT DOESN'T WORK.
INDEED. FASCINATING.
IT WAS OUR LAST CHANCE.
CAPTAIN, YOU DON'T SEEM
TO UNDERSTAND.
IT DID NOT FUNCTION,
BUT IT MUST FUNCTION.
NOTHING COULD GO WRONG,
CAPTAIN. IT SHOULD WORK.
A SCIENTIFIC FACT...
BUT IF THE TRANQUILIZER
DOES NOT FUNCTION,
WHICH IS CLEARLY IMPOSSIBLE,
THEN A RADICAL ALTERATION
OF OUR THOUGHT PATTERNS
MUST BE IN ORDER.
WE NEED A WEAPON.
AN ANSWER.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT THAT NOW, JIM.
LOOK AT THE CLOCK.
10 MINUTES...
AND IT'S ALL GOING TO
END AT THE O.K. CORRAL.
WELL, WE'RE GOING TO
WAIT RIGHT HERE
UNTIL WELL AFTER 5:00.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO
MOVE FROM THIS SPOT.
[THUNDER]
[HORSE NEIGHS]
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
SCOTTY, BONES.
WE'RE TRAPPED.
THEY GOT THEIR WAY.
WE BETTER
STAND AND FIGHT.
GOOD. IF THEY
WANT A FIGHT,
LET'S GIVE THEM
A FIGHT.
THEY'RE EXPERTS
AT GUNFIGHTING.
WE DON'T HAVE
A CHANCE.
THEN WE'D BETTER
BECOME EXPERTS, AND FAST.
THAT MAY NOT
BE NECESSARY.
SPOCK, YOU'VE
GOT SOMETHING?
THE FACTS, CAPTAIN.
PHYSICAL LAWS SIMPLY
CANNOT BE IGNORED.
EXISTENCE CANNOT BE
WITHOUT THEM.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
SPOCK?
I MEAN, DOCTOR,
THAT WE ARE FACED
WITH A STAGGERING
CONTRADICTION.
THE TRANQUILIZER
YOU CREATED
SHOULD HAVE BEEN EFFECTIVE.
IT WOULD HAVE
BEEN EFFECTIVE
ANYWHERE ELSE.
EXACTLY.
DOCTOR, IN YOUR OPINION,
WHAT KILLED MR. CHEKOV?
A PIECE OF LEAD
IN HIS BODY.
WRONG.
HIS MIND KILLED HIM.
COME ON, SPOCK, IF YOU'VE
GOT THE ANSWER, TELL US.
PHYSICAL REALITY
IS CONSISTENT
WITH UNIVERSAL LAWS.
WHERE THE LAWS
DO NOT OPERATE,
THERE IS NO REALITY.
ALL OF THIS...
IS UNREAL.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
UNREAL?
I EXAMINED CHEKOV.
HE'S DEAD.
BUT YOU MADE
YOUR EXAMINATION
UNDER CONDITIONS
WHICH WE CANNOT TRUST.
WE JUDGE REALITY
BY THE RESPONSE
OF OUR SENSES.
ONCE WE ARE CONVINCED
OF THE REALITY
OF A GIVEN SITUATION,
WE ABIDE BY ITS RULES.
WE JUDGED THE BULLETS
TO BE SOLID,
THE GUNS TO BE REAL,
THEREFORE THEY CAN KILL.
CHEKOV IS DEAD
BECAUSE HE BELIEVED
THE BULLETS
WOULD KILL HIM.
HE MAY INDEED BE DEAD.
WE DO NOT KNOW.
BUT WE DO KNOW
THAT THE MELKOTIANS
CREATED THE SITUATION.
IF WE DO NOT
ALLOW OURSELVES
TO BELIEVE THAT
THE BULLETS ARE REAL,
THEY CANNOT KILL US!
EXACTLY.
I KNOW THE BULLETS
ARE UNREAL,
THEREFORE
THEY CANNOT HARM ME.
WE MUST ALL BE
AS CERTAIN AS
YOU ARE, MR. SPOCK,
IF WE'RE TO
SAVE OUR LIVES.
PRECISELY.
BUT THAT'S
NOT POSSIBLE.
THERE'D ALWAYS BE
SOME DOUBT.
THE SMALLEST DOUBT
WOULD BE ENOUGH TO KILL YOU.
WE'RE JUST
HUMAN BEINGS, SPOCK.
WE DON'T HAVE
THAT CLOCKWORK TICKER
IN OUR HEAD
LIKE YOU DO.
WE CAN'T JUST TURN IT
ON AND OFF.
WE MUST.
SPOCK, A VULCAN
MIND MELD.
VERY WELL, SIR.
ENGINEER...
[THUNDER]
[CLOCK STRIKES THE HOUR]
YOUR MIND TO MY MIND...
YOUR THOUGHTS
TO MY THOUGHTS.
[THUNDER]
THE BULLETS
ARE UNREAL...
WITHOUT BODY.
THEY ARE
ILLUSIONS ONLY.
SHADOWS...
WITHOUT SUBSTANCE.
THEY WILL NOT
PASS THROUGH YOUR BODY
FOR THEY
DO NOT EXIST.
THEY...
DO NOT...
EXIST.
[THUNDER]
UNREAL.
APPEARANCES ONLY.
THEY ARE SHADOWS.
ILLUSIONS.
NOTHING BUT GHOSTS
OF REALITY.
THEY ARE LIES...
FALSEHOODS...
SPECTRES WITHOUT BODY.
THEY ARE TO BE IGNORED.
[THUNDER]
CAPTAIN.
DRAW.
CAPTAIN, I...
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NEITHER DO I.
HE'S IN PERFECT HEALTH.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE HAVE I BEEN?
RIGHT HERE, IT SEEMS.
BUT THAT GIRL...
SHE WAS
SO BEAUTIFUL,
SO REAL.
DO YOU REMEMBER
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO.
GOOD. PERHAPS THAT EXPLAINS
WHY HE'S HERE.
NOTHING WAS REAL TO HIM
EXCEPT THE GIRL.
CAPTAIN.
THE MELKOTIAN OBJECT.
SENSOR READINGS.
THE OBJECT IS BEGINNING
TO EMIT M-RAYS
OF A HIGHLY UNSTABLE
NATURE, CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT,
SOUND RED ALERT.
MR. CHEKOV,
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS
ON FULL.
PHASER GUN CREWS,
LOCK ON TARGET.
ENERGY OUTPUT INCREASING
BEYOND MEASURABLE LEVELS,
CAPTAIN.
PHASER GUNS,
STAND BY TO FIRE.
[INDISTINCT P.A.]
IT'S...
GONE, SIR.
DAMAGE REPORT,
LIEUTENANT.
NO DAMAGE, SIR.
ALL DECKS REPORT
FULLY OPERATIONAL.
CAPTAIN KIRK...
YOU DID NOT KILL.
IS THIS THE WAY
OF YOUR KIND?
IT IS.
WE FIGHT ONLY
WHEN THERE'S NO CHOICE.
WE PREFER THE WAYS
OF PEACEFUL CONTACT.
I SPEAK FOR A VAST ALLIANCE
OF FELLOW CREATURES
WHO BELIEVE IN
THE SAME THING.
WE HAVE SOUGHT YOU OUT
TO JOIN US.
OUR MISSION
IS STILL ONE OF PEACE.
APPROACH OUR PLANET
AND BE WELCOME.
A DELEGATION
WILL COME OUT TO MEET YOU.
OUR WARNING THREATS
ARE OVER.
EXCELLENT.
LIEUTENANT,
CANCEL RED ALERT.
MR. CHEKOV, RESUME
ORIGINAL COURSE,
WARP FACTOR 2.
WARP FACTOR 2,
SIR.
CAPTAIN.
MAY I
ASK A QUESTION?
YOU NEEDN'T ANSWER
IF IT SEEMS
TOO PERSONAL.
I'M SURE I'LL BE ABLE
TO GIVE YOU AN ANSWER,
MR. SPOCK.
THIS AFTERNOON,
YOU WANTED TO KILL,
DIDN'T YOU?
BUT HE DIDN'T KILL,
MR. SPOCK.
BUT HE WANTED TO,
DOCTOR.
IS THAT THE WAY
IT SEEMED TO YOU, MR. SPOCK?
YES, CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK...
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THAT'S EXACTLY
THE WAY IT WAS.
MANKIND...
READY TO KILL.
THAT'S THE WAY IT WAS
IN 1881.
I WONDER
HOW HUMANITY
MANAGED TO SURVIVE.
WE OVERCAME OUR INSTINCT
FOR VIOLENCE.