REPORT, MR. CHEKOV.
FULL SCAN.
RESULTS--NEGATIVE.
RADIATION LEVEL--NORMAL.
ATMOSPHERE AND TERRAIN
ARE UNDISTURBED.
NO EVIDENCE OF A COLONY
NOR ANY RESIDUAL
AFTEREFFECT OF A FORCE
THAT MIGHT HAVE
ANNIHILATED IT.
LIFE READINGS, DR. McCOY?
NOTHING. THEY SAID
THEY WERE
BEING ATTACKED
BY AN UNIDENTIFIED SHIP.
WHICH WE WERE UNABLE TO
DETECT UPON APPROACH.
AN ENTIRE HUMAN COLONY.
A WHOLE SETTLEMENT.
100 MEN, WOMEN,
AND CHILDREN.
WHO DID IT?
AND WHY?
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS HAVE PICKED UP
A KLINGON SHIP,
CLOSING FAST.
DEFLECTORS ON.
CONDITION RED.
PROTECT YOURSELVES.
TOTAL REPLY
IF ATTACKED.
SO THAT'S THE ANSWER--
KLINGONS.
TROUBLE ABOARD
THE KLINGON SHIP.
EVIDENCE OF EXPLOSIONS,
MASSIVE DESTRUCTION.
CAPTAIN, THE ENEMY SHIP
IS DRIFTING,
TOTALLY DISABLED,
AND WE NEVER FIRED
UPON HER.
MAINTAIN RED ALERT.
[FOOTSTEPS]
YOU ATTACKED MY SHIP!
400 OF MY CREW DEAD.
KIRK, MY SHIP IS DISABLED.
I CLAIM YOURS.
YOU ARE NOW PRISONERS
OF THE KLINGON EMPIRE
AGAINST WHICH YOU'VE COMMITTED
A WANTON ACT OF WAR!
Kirk: SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
FOR 3 YEARS,
THE FEDERATION AND
THE KLINGON EMPIRE
HAVE BEEN AT PEACE,
A TREATY WE HAVE HONORED
TO THE LETTER.
WE TOOK NO ACTION
AGAINST YOUR SHIP, KANG.
WERE THE SCREAMS
OF MY CREW IMAGINARY?
WHAT WERE YOUR
ORDERS, KIRK?
TO START A WAR?
YOU'VE SUCCEEDED.
TO TEST A NEW WEAPON?
WE SHALL BE HAPPY
TO EXAMINE IT.
THERE WAS A FEDERATION
COLONY ON THIS PLANET.
IT WAS DESTROYED.
BY WHAT?
NO BODIES,
NO RUINS.
A COLONY
OF THE INVISIBLE?
YES, A TEST OF A NEW
KLINGON WEAPON,
LEAVING NO TRACES.
FEDERATION SHIPS
DON'T SPECIALIZE
IN SNEAK ATTACKS.
WE HAVE WONDERED
WHEN YOU WOULD BEGIN.
YOU LURED MY SHIP
INTO AMBUSH
BY A FALSE KLINGON
DISTRESS CALL.
YOU WILL TELL US WHY
WITH THE PROPER PERSUASION.
YOU RECEIVED
A DISTRESS CALL?
WE RECEIVED
A DISTRESS CALL.
I DON'T PROPOSE TO SPEND
THE REST OF MY LIFE
ON THIS BALL OF DUST,
ARGUING YOUR FANTASIES.
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS MINE!
INSTRUCT YOUR TRANSPORTER
ROOM TO BEAM US ABOARD.
GO TO THE DEVIL.
WE HAVE NO DEVIL, KIRK.
BUT WE UNDERSTAND
THE HABITS OF YOURS.
I SHALL TORTURE YOU...
TO DEATH...
ONE BY ONE...
UNTIL YOUR NOBLE CAPTAIN
CRIES "ENOUGH."
WHO WILL BE FIRST?
COSSACKS!
FILTHY KLINGON MURDERERS!
YOU KILLED
MY BROTHER PIOTRE.
THE ARCANIS 4 RESEARCH
OUTPOST.
100 PEACEFUL PEOPLE
MASSACRED!
JUST LIKE YOU DID HERE.
MY BROTHER--YOU KILLED HIM.
AND YOU VOLUNTEER
TO JOIN HIM.
THAT IS LOYALTY.
AAH!
CHEKOV!
STOP THE TORTURE!
JIM, YOU CAN'T HAND OVER
THE "ENTERPRISE."
HELP CHEKOV.
DON'T PLAN ANY TRICKS,
KIRK.
I WILL KILL 100 HOSTAGES
AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF TREACHERY.
I'LL BEAM YOU ABOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
ONCE THERE, NO TRICKS.
Chekov: CAPTAIN,
YOU CAN'T.
DON'T LET THESE ANIMALS
HAVE THE SHIP.
MOVE ASIDE.
Kang: ANIMALS?
YOUR CAPTAIN
CRAWLS LIKE ONE.
A KLINGON WOULD NEVER
HAVE SURRENDERED.
ORDER EVERYBODY IN THIS AREA
TO BE TRANSPORTED UP.
ALL WEAPONS ON HIM.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
MR. SPOCK.
HERE, CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK,
WE HAVE GUESTS.
ADJUST TRANSPORTER
TO WIDE FIELD.
BEAM UP EVERYONE
IN THE TARGET AREA.
UNDERSTOOD, CAPTAIN.
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
FULL SECURITY, JOHNSON,
ON THE DOUBLE.
GOOD WORK, SPOCK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
OUR LANDING PARTY
IS INTACT, DOCTOR.
ALL OTHERS SUSPENDED
IN TRANSIT.
WHO ARE THE GUESTS,
BY THE WAY?
KLINGONS.
WELL, THEY'RE RIGHT
IN HERE.
JOHNSON?
SECURITY ON THE WAY, SIR.
CAPTAIN, LEAVE THEM
WHERE THEY ARE--
NONEXISTENCE.
THAT'S SO MANY LESS
KLINGON MONSTERS
IN THE GALAXY.
BRING THEM IN.
MOVE 'EM OUT. MOVE!
LIAR!
I SAID NO TRICKS AFTER
WE REACH THE SHIP.
YOU'RE A PRISONER
OF THE FEDERATION OF PLANETS
AGAINST WHICH YOU MAY
OR MAY NOT
HAVE COMMITTED
AN ACT OF WAR.
THERE ARE STILL
SURVIVORS ABOARD
MY SHIP.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE NOT BEEN
ABLE TO GET THROUGH
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
ALL SUBSPACE FREQUENCIES
HAVE BEEN BLOCKED,
AND THERE'S TOO MUCH RADIATION
COMING FROM THAT KLINGON SHIP.
IT'S A HAZARD
TO THE VICINITY.
PREPARE TO DESTRUCT.
COMPLETING THE JOB
YOU STARTED?
YOU WOULDN'T BE STANDING
HERE IF I HAD.
FIRST GROUP FROM
THE KLINGON VESSEL,
CAPTAIN.
MY WIFE MARA
AND MY SCIENCE OFFICER.
KANG, WHAT HAS HAPPENED?
MORE FEDERATION
TREACHERY.
WE ARE PRISONERS.
WHAT WILL THEY DO TO US?
I'VE HEARD OF
THEIR ATROCITIES,
THEIR DEATH CAMPS.
THEY WILL TORTURE US
FOR OUR SCIENTIFIC AND
MILITARY INFORMATION.
APPARENTLY YOU HAVE
A FEW THINGS
TO LEARN ABOUT US.
DETAIN THEM
IN THE CREW LOUNGE.
PROGRAM
THE FOOD SYNTHESIZER
TO ACCOMMODATE
OUR GUESTS.
YOU'LL BE WELL-TREATED,
KANG.
SO I HAVE SEEN.
SECURE FROM RED ALERT.
BUT MAINTAIN
GENERAL QUARTERS.
SCAN THIS SECTOR
FOR OTHER SHIPS.
RUN A FULL CHECK
ON THE COLONY.
I WANT THIS THING
NAILED DOWN FAST.
WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT DISTRESS CALL.
AT THE MOMENT
WE RECEIVED
THE DISTRESS SIGNAL
FROM THE COLONY
ON BETA 12-A,
THE KLINGONS WERE
TOO FAR DISTANT
TO HAVE BEEN
THE ATTACKERS.
MOREOVER, THEY ALSO WERE
APPARENTLY ATTRACTED
BY A DISTRESS CALL.
LIES. THEY WANT
TO START A WAR
BY PRETENDING
THAT WE DID.
CHEKOV MAY BE RIGHT.
THE KLINGONS CLAIM
TO HAVE HONORED
THE TRUCE,
BUT THERE HAVE
BEEN INCIDENTS,
RAIDS ON
OUR OUTPOSTS.
NO PROOF THAT
THE KLINGONS
COMMITTED IT.
WHAT PROOF
DO WE NEED?
WE KNOW
WHAT A KLINGON IS.
OUR LOG TAPES WILL
INDICATE OUR INNOCENCE
IN THE PRESENT SITUATION.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE
THAT THEY WILL
BE BELIEVED.
REPORT.
STILL NO CONTACT WITH
STARFLEET COMMAND, SIR.
OUTSIDE COMMUNICATIONS
BLANKETED.
KEEP TRYING. WE'VE GOT
A DIPLOMATIC TIGER
BY THE TAIL.
Scotty:
TRANSPORTER ROOM
TO BRIDGE.
KLINGON SHIP
IS VACATED, SIR.
VERY GOOD, SCOTTY.
MR. SULU?
FORWARD PHASERS
LOCKED AND READY
TO FIRE, SIR.
FIRE PHASERS.
SENSOR SWEEPS
REVEAL NO OTHER SHIPS
WITHIN RANGE, CAPTAIN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA?
NO CONTACT
WITH STARFLEET
AS YET, SIR.
MR. SULU, CHANGE COURSE
TO 17 MARK 4,
WARP FACTOR 3.
WARP FACTOR 3, SIR.
WHEN I TAKE THIS SHIP,
I'LL HAVE KIRK'S HEAD
STUFFED AND HUNG
ON HIS CABIN WALL.
THEY WILL KILL US
BEFORE WE CAN ACT.
NO, THEY WISH
TO QUESTION US,
LEARN OUR STRENGTH,
OUR PLANS.
THEY NEVER WILL.
WE ARE 40 AGAINST 400.
4,000 THROATS
MAY BE CUT
IN ONE NIGHT
BY
A RUNNING MAN.
PATIENCE. VIGILANCE.
THEY WILL MAKE
THEIR MISTAKE.
CAPTURE OF THE "ENTERPRISE"
WILL GIVE US KNOWLEDGE
TO END THIS WAR QUICKLY.
CAPTAIN!
THIS DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
CARRIERS ARE NORMAL.
CHANNELS ARE OPEN.
THERE'S STILL NO
OUTSIDE CONTACT!
I DON'T
UNDERSTAND IT, SIR.
COULD THE KLINGONS
BE DOING SOMETHING?
SULU?
CHANGE IN COURSE,
ACCELERATING.
HELM DEAD.
AUXILIARY NAVIGATION
DEAD.
OVERRIDE.
NOTHING RESPONDS,
CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, STOP ALL ENGINES.
I WOULD IF I COULD, SIR,
BUT THE CONTROLS
HAVE GONE CRAZY.
SOMETHING'S TAKEN OVER.
SCOTTY!
THE ENGINES, SIR.
THEY'VE GONE TO WARP 9
BY THEMSELVES!
NEW COURSE?
Sulu:
9-0-2, MARK 5.
THAT'LL TAKE US
OUT OF THE GALAXY.
CAPTAIN, REPORTS COMING IN
FROM THE LOWER DECKS.
EMERGENCY BULKHEADS
HAVE CLOSED.
ALMOST 400 CREWMEN ARE
TRAPPED DOWN THERE, SIR.
MOST INTERESTING.
THE BULK OF
YOUR CREW TRAPPED,
YOUR SHIP RACING
FROM THIS GALAXY
AT WILD SPEEDS?
DELIGHTFUL.
HOW DID I PERFORM
THIS SABOTAGE, KIRK?
ALL MY MEN ARE HERE.
JOHNSON.
GET DOWN TO SECURITY.
SEARCH EVERY SECTION.
SOME KLINGONS MAY HAVE
BEAMED ABOARD UNDETECTED
FROM THE WRECKED SHIP.
THEN GET DOWN TO ENGINEERING
AND HELP SCOTTY
HAMMER THINGS
BACK TO NORMAL.
AND FREE THOSE
TRAPPED CREWMEN.
AND BEFORE I PUT YOU
IN THE BRIG,
THERE'S A LITTLE SOMETHING
I OWE YOU.
PHASERS.
OUT!
STAND AND FIGHT,
YOU COWARD.
SICK BAY.
BRIDGE.
THE KLINGONS ARE FREE.
THEY'RE ARMED AS WE ARE.
THEY'LL TRY
AND TAKE THE SHIP.
SCOTTY, HOW MANY MEN
DO WE HAVE?
Scotty:
392 TRAPPED BELOW DECKS.
DEPLOY FORCES TO PROTECT
YOUR SECTION
AND THE AUXILIARY
CONTROL CENTER.
CHECK THE ARMORY
AND TRY AND FREE
THOSE TRAPPED CREWMEN.
THE DOORS AND BULKHEADS
WON'T BUDGE.
WE'LL HAVE
TO CUT THROUGH.
BLOW OUT THE BULKHEADS
IF YOU HAVE TO.
WE NEED NUMBERS.
WHAT KIND OF LUCK
HAVE YOU HAD CONTROLLING
THE SHIP'S SPEED?
NO, SIR.
SHE'S A PROJECTILE
AT WARP 9.
AND DON'T ASK ME WHAT'S
HOLDING HER TOGETHER.
5-MINUTE REPORT, SCOTTY.
KIRK OUT.
FULL SENSOR SCAN
OF THE SHIP.
REPORT ON ANY MOVEMENT
BY THE KLINGONS.
THE KLINGON EMPIRE
HAS MAINTAINED
A DUELING TRADITION.
THEY THINK THEY CAN
BEAT US WITH SWORDS.
CAPTAIN, NEITHER THE KLINGON
TECHNOLOGY NOR OURS
IS CAPABLE OF THIS--
THE INSTANTANEOUS
TRANSMUTATION OF MATTER.
I DOUBT THAT THEY
ARE RESPONSIBLE.
ANY OTHER
LOGICAL CANDIDATE?
NONE.
HOWEVER, IF THEY HAD
SUCH POWER,
WOULD THEY NOT HAVE USED IT
TO CREATE
MORE EFFECTIVE WEAPONS
AND ONLY FOR THEMSELVES?
MR. SULU.
GET BELOW.
TAKE COMMAND
OF ENGINEERING
AND AUXILIARY CONTROL.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
MR. CHEKOV.
CAPTAIN!
MR. CHEKOV,
AS YOU WERE.
CHEKOV!
SIR, LET ME GO, TOO.
I GOT A PERSONAL SCORE
TO SETTLE WITH THE KLINGONS.
THIS IS NO TIME
FOR A VENDETTA.
MAINTAIN YOUR POST.
CAPTAIN.
CHEKOV, MAINTAIN
YOUR POST.
DON'T TRY TO STOP ME,
CAPTAIN.
I SAW WHAT THEY LEFT
OF PIOTRE,
AND I SWORE ON HIS GRAVE
I WOULD AVENGE
HIS MURDER.
WHAT'S CHEKOV'S GRUDGE
AGAINST THE KLINGONS?
WHO'S PIOTRE?
HIS ONLY BROTHER,
KILLED IN A KLINGON RAID.
HIS BROTHER?
HE NEVER HAD A BROTHER.
HE'S AN ONLY CHILD.
SULU, GET DOWN
TO ENGINEERING.
AYE, SIR.
SECURITY,
THIS IS THE CAPTAIN.
FIND MR. CHEKOV
AND BRING HIM
TO THE BRIDGE.
CAPTAIN, WHY WOULD, WHY WOULD
CHEKOV
BELIEVE HE HAS
A BROTHER?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT HE DOES.
AND NOW HE WANTS REVENGE
FOR A NONEXISTENT LOSS.
THERE.
THOSE FILTHY BUTCHERS.
THERE ARE RULES, EVEN IN WAR.
YOU DON'T KEEP HACKING
AT A MAN AFTER HE'S DOWN.
HAND ME THAT
NUMANOL CAPSULE.
LAYOUT AND SPECIFICATIONS
OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
COMMANDER.
ENEMY NUMBERS ARE
THE SAME AS OURS.
WE HAVE
A FIGHTING BALANCE.
THEN WE TAKE THE SHIP.
A SHIP THAT IS HEADED
TOWARDS THE END
OF THE GALAXY?
IN TIME, IN TIME.
WE MUST TAKE THESE SECTIONS.
FIRST--ENGINEERING.
Kirk: KIRK HERE.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
THERE'S NO USE TRYING TO FREE
THOSE MEN DOWN BELOW.
THE PHASER TORCHES, THEY WON'T
CUT THROUGH THE BULKHEADS,
NOR THE DOORS,
NOR THE DECKS.
THERE'S SOMETHING
HAPPENED TO THE METAL.
Kirk: WHAT ABOUT
THE ARMORY?
I'M THERE NOW, SIR,
AND YOU NEVER SAW
SUCH A FINE COLLECTION
OF ANTIQUES IN YOUR LIFE.
GET BACK
TO ENGINEERING.
TRY AND RE-ESTABLISH
ENGINE CONTROL,
AND TALK TO
ORDNANCE ABOUT
MANUFACTURING PHASER
REPLACEMENTS.
AYE, SIR.
A CLAYMORE.
YOU'RE A BEAUTY.
WHAT IN BLAZES
IS GOING ON?
SCANS INDICATE
THAT OUR FORCES
AND THOSE OF
THE KLINGONS
ARE EXACTLY EQUAL
AT 38 EACH.
THE KLINGONS
CONTROL DECK 6
AND STARBOARD
DECK 7
WHILE WE CONTROL
ALL SECTIONS ABOVE.
CONSTANT SURVEILLANCE,
MR. SPOCK.
MOST CURIOUS, CAPTAIN.
THERE APPEAR TO BE MORE
LIFE-ENERGY UNITS ON BOARD
THAN CAN BE ACCOUNTED FOR
BY THE PRESENCE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE" CREW
PLUS THE KLINGONS.
A CONSIDERABLE DISCREPANCY.
COULD MORE KLINGONS
HAVE BEAMED ABOARD?
I SHALL ATTEMPT
A COMPENSATORY READING
OF KLINGON UNITS.
ANY SIGNS OF THOSE
DEVILS, MR. SULU?
ALL CLEAR, MR. SCOTT.
THEY'VE TAKEN
ENGINEERING.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
MORE OF THOSE KLINGONS
ARE AROUND,
BUT WE'LL SPLIT UP HERE
AND TRY TO MAKE IT BACK
TO THE BRIDGE.
AYE.
VICTORY!
NO ADDITIONAL KLINGONS
DETECTED, CAPTAIN.
IT IS AN ALIEN LIFE FORCE,
A SINGLE ENTITY.
AN ALIEN LIFE FORCE.
WE MUST MAKE CONTACT,
FIND OUT WHAT IT WANTS.
READINGS BEING DIVERTED
TO THE LIBRARY COMPUTER
FOR ANALYSIS.
COMPUTER, REPORT.
Computer voice:
ALIEN LIFE FORCE ON BOARD
IS COMPOSED OF PURE ENERGY.
TYPE UNKNOWN.
ACTIONS INDICATE
INTELLIGENCE AND PURPOSE.
WHAT PURPOSE?
INSUFFICIENT DATA
FOR FURTHER ANALYSIS.
A BROTHER THAT
NEVER EXISTED.
A PHANTOM COLONY.
IMAGINARY
DISTRESS CALLS.
THE CREATION OF
THESE...WEAPONS.
DO YOU SENSE
A PATTERN,
MR. SPOCK?
IF THE ALIEN IS CREATING
THESE EVENTS, CAPTAIN,
IT IS APPARENTLY CAPABLE
OF MANIPULATING
MATTER AND MIND.
AND NOW IT HAS CONTROL
OF THE "ENTERPRISE"
AND TAKING US
OUT OF THE GALAXY.
BUT WHY?
CAPTAIN, I AM CONSTRAINED
TO POINT OUT
THAT SINCE MINDS
ARE EVIDENTLY
BEING INFLUENCED,
WE CANNOT KNOW
AT THIS MOMENT
WHETHER OUR OWN MEMORIES
ARE COMPLETELY ACCURATE
AND TRUE.
WE MUST TALK TO KANG,
BURY THE HATCHET.
AN APPROPRIATE
CHOICE OF TERMS, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, IT IS
NOTORIOUSLY DIFFICULT
TO ARRANGE A TRUCE
WITH THE KLINGONS
ONCE BLOOD HAS BEEN DRAWN.
TRUCE?
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
I'VE GOT MEN
IN SICK BAY,
SOME OF THEM DYING.
ATROCITIES COMMITTED
ON THEIR PERSONS,
AND YOU TALK ABOUT
MAKING PEACE
WITH THESE FIENDS?
IF OUR BACKS
WERE TURNED,
THEY'D JUMP US
IN A MINUTE.
AND YOU KNOW
WHAT KLINGONS DO
TO PRISONERS--
SLAVE LABOR,
DEATH PLANETS,
EXPERIMENTS!
McCOY...
WHILE YOU'RE
TALKING,
THEY'RE PLANNING
ATTACKS.
THIS IS A FIGHT
TO THE DEATH.
WE'D BETTER START
TRYING TO WIN IT!
WE ARE ATTEMPTING
TO END IT, DOCTOR,
BY REASON, PREFERABLY.
THERE IS AN ALIEN ON BOARD
WHICH MAY HAVE CREATED
THIS SITUATION.
WHO CARES WHAT
STARTED IT,
MR. SPOCK?
WE'RE IN IT!
THOSE MURDERERS.
WE SHOULD WIPE OUT
EVERY ONE OF THEM!
THE ALIEN
IS THE REAL THREAT.
THAT'S THE ENEMY
WE HAVE TO WIPE OUT.
SICK BAY CALLING, DOCTOR.
THERE ARE MORE WOUNDED MEN
REQUIRING YOUR ATTENTION.
HOW MANY MORE MEN
MUST DIE
BEFORE YOU TWO
BEGIN TO ACT LIKE
MILITARY MEN
INSTEAD OF FOOLS?
[INTERCOM SIGNAL]
KIRK HERE.
THIS IS KANG.
KANG, THERE'S
SOMETHING IMPORTANT
I MUST DISCUSS WITH YOU.
I HAVE CAPTURED YOUR
ENGINEERING SECTION
AND NOW CONTROL
THIS SHIP'S POWER
AND LIFE-SUPPORT
SYSTEMS.
I HAVE DEPRIVED
ALL AREAS
EXCEPT OUR OWN.
YOU WILL DIE
OF SUFFOCATION
IN THE ICY COLD
OF SPACE.
THE ENTERPRISE IS HEADING
OUT OF OUR GALAXY,
CONTROLLED BY
A MYSTERIOUS ALIEN
SOMEWHERE ABOARD THE SHIP.
ENGINEERING HAS BEEN
TAKEN OVER BY KLINGONS
WHO HAVE CUT OFF
LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
MR. SULU.
CAPTAIN.
GET DOWN TO EMERGENCY
MANUAL CONTROL.
TRY TO PROTECT OUR LIFE-SUPPORT
CIRCUITS AND AUXILIARY POWER.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
SIR. CHEKOV WAS RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
SCOTTY, I'M GLAD
YOU'VE COME.
WE SHOULD HAVE LEFT
THOSE FUZZ-FACED GOONS
IN THE TRANSPORTER.
THAT'S RIGHT
WHERE THEY BELONG!
SCOTTY.
NONEXISTENCE!
NOW THEY CAN STUDY
THE "ENTERPRISE,"
ADD OUR TECHNOLOGY
TO THEIRS,
CHANGE THE BALANCE
OF POWER.
YOU'VE JEOPARDIZED
THE FEDERATION!
SCOTTY.
EASY, MR. SCOTT.
KEEP YOUR VULCAN HANDS
OFF ME.
JUST KEEP AWAY!
YOUR FEELINGS
MIGHT BE HURT,
YOU GREEN-BLOODED
HALF-BREED!
MAY I SAY THAT I HAVE
NOT THOROUGHLY ENJOYED
SERVING WITH HUMANS?
I FIND THEIR ILLOGIC
AND FOOLISH EMOTIONS
A CONSTANT IRRITANT.
THEN TRANSFER OUT! FREAK!
GENTLEMEN!
SPOCK!
SCOTTY.
SPOCK. SPOCK!
STOP IT!
YOU'RE HALF HUMAN!
WHAT ARE WE SAYING?
WHAT ARE WE DOING
TO EACH OTHER?
FASCINATING.
A RESULT OF STRESS?
WE'VE BEEN UNDER
STRESS BEFORE.
IT'S NEVER SET US
AT EACH OTHER'S
THROATS.
BUT THIS IS WAR.
THERE ISN'T
ANY WAR!
OR IS THERE?
HAVE WE FORGOTTEN
HOW TO DEFEND OURSELVES?
SCOTTY.
WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO US?
WE'VE BEEN
TRAINED TO THINK
IN OTHER TERMS
THAN WAR.
WE'VE BEEN TRAINED
TO FIGHT ITS CAUSES,
IF NECESSARY.
THEN WHY ARE
WE BEHAVING
LIKE A GROUP
OF SAVAGES?
LOOK AT ME.
TWO FORCES
ABOARD THIS SHIP,
EACH OF THEM
EQUALLY ARMED.
HAS A WAR BEEN
STAGED FOR US,
COMPLETE
WITH WEAPONS
AND IDEOLOGY
AND PATRIOTIC
DRUM-BEATING?
EVEN...
SPOCK.
RACE HATRED?
RECENT EVENTS WOULD
SEEM TO BE DIRECTED
TOWARD A MAGNIFICATION
OF THE BASIC HOSTILITIES
BETWEEN HUMANS
AND KLINGONS.
APPARENTLY, IT IS BY DESIGN
THAT WE FIGHT.
WE SEEM TO BE PAWNS.
BUT WHAT'S THE GAME?
AND WHOSE?
AND WHAT ARE
THE RULES?
IT IS MOST URGENT
THAT WE LOCATE
THE ALIEN ENTITY IMMEDIATELY
AND DETERMINE ITS MOTIVES
AND A METHOD FOR HALTING
ITS ACTIVITIES.
WITHOUT SENSORS?
ALL OUR POWER DOWN?
THIS THING
COULD GO ANYWHERE.
YES.
MR. SULU, REPORT.
NO GOOD, CAPTAIN.
CIRCUITS ARE IN,
BUT SYSTEMS JUST
AREN'T RESPONDING.
WE'RE GETTING SOMETHING.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
POWER AND LIFE-SUPPORT
RESTORED.
REMOTE'S ON STANDBY.
GOOD WORK.
BUT, CAPTAIN,
I DIDN'T DO IT.
EVERYTHING JUST
CAME ON BY ITSELF.
THEIR LIFE-SUPPORT SYSTEMS
HAVE RESUMED.
SENSORS MAY BE OPERATING.
START SCANNING.
LET'S FIND THAT ALIEN.
HOLDING STEADY.
CAUSE THEM
TO BE UNSTEADY.
THEY APPEAR
TO BE CONTROLLED
FROM ANOTHER LOCATION.
ALSO UNABLE TO AFFECT
SHIP'S COURSE
FOR RETURN
TO OUR EMPIRE.
ONE OF KIRK'S TRICKS.
COULD HE BYPASS
THIS CIRCUIT?
WHAT POWER IS IT THAT
SUPPORTS OUR BATTLE
YET STARVES OUR VICTORY?
POWER. INTERRUPT IT
AT THEIR MAIN
LIFE-SUPPORT COUPLINGS.
WHERE?
NUMBER 6 DECK.
COME.
ALIEN DETECTED
IN THE ENGINEERING SECTION,
NEAR REACTOR NUMBER 3.
LET'S GO.
YOU DON'T DIE YET.
YOU'RE NOT HUMAN...
BUT YOU'RE VERY BEAUTIFUL.
VERY...
BEAUTIFUL.
CHEKOV!
JIM, HE'S NOT RESPONSIBLE.
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
THERE'S A-AN ALIEN ENTITY
ABOARD THE SHIP.
IT'S FORCING US TO FIGHT.
WE DON'T WANT TO.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
ITS MOTIVE IS.
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT.
YOU MUST HELP US.
TAKE ME TO KANG.
A TEMPORARY TRUCE,
THAT'S ALL I ASK.
SPOCK, TAKE HER.
CHEKOV.
IS THIS WHAT'S
IN STORE FOR US,
FROM HERE ON IN?
VIOLENCE,
HATRED.
BRAIN WAVES SHOW
ALMOST PARANOID MANIA.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE LOST CONTROL.
SO DID I.
WE'RE BECOMING
ANIMAL WARRIORS.
LET'S GO, SPOCK.
ORDERLY.
JIM.
JOHNSON'S
HEART WOUND
IS ALMOST
COMPLETELY HEALED.
THE SAME
WITH THE OTHER
CASUALTIES.
SWORD WOUNDS
IN THE VITAL ORGANS,
MASSIVE TRAUMA,
SHOCK--
THEY'RE ALL HEALING
AT A FANTASTIC RATE.
IT WOULD APPEAR
THAT THE ENTITY
WANTS US ALIVE.
WHY? SO WE CAN FIGHT
AND FIGHT AND KEEP
COMING BACK FOR MORE
LIKE SOME BLOODY COLISEUM?
WHAT'S NEXT,
THE ROAR OF CROWDS?
PERHAPS HUMAN AND KLINGON
PSYCHOLOGIES
AND COMBAT CAPABILITIES
ARE BEING TESTED
BY AN ALIEN WITH DESIGNS
ON BOTH POWERS.
GENTLEMEN,
IF WE ARE PAWNS,
YOU'RE LOOKING
AT ONE WHO IS
EXTREMELY SORRY.
I UNDERSTAND, DOCTOR.
I, TOO, FELT A BRIEF SURGE
OF RACIAL BIGOTRY.
MOST DISTASTEFUL.
LET'S FIND THE ALIEN.
YOU COME WITH US.
MAYBE WE CAN PROVE TO YOU
THAT IT EXISTS.
WHAT IS IT?
TOTALLY UNFAMILIAR.
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
REPORTING FOR DUTY, SIR.
DUTY? DID McCOY RELEASE
YOU FROM SICK BAY?
I RELEASED MYSELF.
THEN GET BACK
TO SICK BAY!
NOT ON YOUR LIFE, SIR.
I'M FIT AND READY
FOR ACTION.
KLINGONS ALMOST
DID ME IN ONCE.
I'M OUT
TO EVEN THE SCORE.
I ORDER YOU--
I'VE GOT MY ORDERS.
I'M OBEYING ORDERS!
KILL THE KLINGONS!
IT'S THEM OR US,
ISN'T IT?
JOHNSON!
UH!
FASCINATING.
DURING
LIEUTENANT JOHNSON'S
EMOTIONAL OUTBURST,
HIS EXPRESSION
OF HATRED AND LUST
FOR VENGEANCE,
THE ALIEN'S
LIFE ENERGY LEVEL
INCREASED.
WHEN THE LIEUTENANT
BECAME UNCONSCIOUS,
THE ALIEN
LOST ENERGY.
IT SUBSISTS
ON THE EMOTIONS OF OTHERS.
THIS ONE APPEARS
TO BE STRENGTHENED
BY MENTAL RADIATIONS
OF HOSTILITY,
VIOLENT INTENTIONS.
IT EXISTS ON THE HATE
OF OTHERS.
TO PUT IT SIMPLY.
AND IT HAS ACTED
AS A CATALYST,
CREATING
THIS SITUATION
IN ORDER TO SATISFY
THAT NEED.
IT HAS BROUGHT
TOGETHER
OPPOSING FORCES,
PROVIDED
CRUDE INSTRUMENTS
IN AN EFFORT
TO PROMOTE
THE MOST VIOLENT
MODE OF CONFLICT.
AND KEPT NUMBERS
AND RESOURCES BALANCED
SO THAT IT CAN MAINTAIN
A CONSTANT STATE
OF VIOLENCE.
IT'S GOT TO HAVE
A VULNERABLE AREA.
WE'VE GOT TO GET RID OF IT.
THEN ALL HOSTILE
ATTITUDES ON BOARD
MUST BE ELIMINATED.
THE FIGHTING
MUST END AND SOON.
OR WE'RE A DOOMED SHIP,
TRAVELING FOREVER
BETWEEN GALAXIES,
FILLED WITH ETERNAL
BLOOD LUST,
ETERNAL WARFARE.
KANG HAS GOT TO LISTEN.
WE'VE GOT TO POOL
OUR KNOWLEDGE
AND GET RID OF THIS THING.
KANG.
KANG, THIS IS
CAPTAIN KIRK.
KANG, DO YOU READ ME?
COMMANDER!
IT'S A TRICK!
KANG.
HE WON'T ANSWER.
THE ALIEN IS AFFECTING
HIS MIND, CAPTAIN.
SOON IT WILL BECOME
SO POWERFUL
THAT NONE OF US WILL BE
ABLE TO RESIST IT.
[INTERCOM SIGNAL]
SCOTTY, SIR.
THE SHIP'S DILITHIUM CRYSTALS
ARE DETERIORATING.
WE CAN'T STOP THE PROCESS.
TIME FACTOR?
IN 12 MINUTES,
WE'LL BE TOTALLY
WITHOUT ENGINE POWER.
WELL...
DO WHATEVER YOU CAN.
KIRK OUT.
AND SO WE DRIFT
IN SPACE
WITH ONLY HATRED
AND BLOODSHED
ABOARD.
NOW DO YOU
BELIEVE?
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE...
ARMAGEDDON.
WE MUST FIND A WAY
TO DEFEAT
THE ALIEN FORCE OF HATE
THAT HAS TAKEN OVER
THE ENTERPRISE,
STOP THE WAR NOW,
OR SPEND ETERNITY
IN FUTILE BLOODY VIOLENCE.
THERE'S NO CHANGE,
CAPTAIN.
THE DILITHIUM
CRYSTALS ARE
DISCHARGING.
THERE'S NOTHING
WE CAN DO ABOUT IT.
IF I COULD TALK TO KANG...
SOMEHOW CUT THROUGH
THE KLINGON LINES,
MAKE PEACE BEFORE
IT'S TOO LATE.
WE HAVE 9 MINUTES,
53 SECONDS TO POWER ZERO.
THERE IS, OF COURSE,
A LOGICAL ALTERNATIVE.
KANG'S WIFE IS, AFTER ALL,
OUR PRISONER.
PERHAPS A THREAT.
AYE.
NOW THAT'S SOMETHING
THE KLINGONS
WOULD UNDERSTAND.
[CLICKS ON INTERCOM]
KANG.
KANG, THIS IS
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I KNOW YOU CAN HEAR ME,
SO DON'T CUT ME OFF.
WE HAVE MARA, YOUR WIFE.
WE TALK TRUCE NOW,
OR SHE DIES. REPLY.
SHE HAS 5 SECONDS
TO LIVE.
REPLY.
SHE IS A VICTIM
OF WAR, CAPTAIN.
SHE UNDERSTANDS.
HE CALLED MY BLUFF.
YOU'RE NOT GOING--
THE FEDERATION DOESN'T
KILL OR MISTREAT
ITS PRISONERS.
YOU'VE BEEN LISTENING
TO PROPAGANDA FABLES.
HOW MUCH TIME?
8 MINUTES, 42 SECONDS.
SO THIS WAS NO TRICK?
IT'S THE ALIEN
THAT'S DONE THIS.
WE'RE
IN ITS POWER,
OUR PEOPLE
AND YOURS.
WE ONLY WANTED TO
STOP THE FIGHTING
TO SAVE US ALL.
WE HAVE ALWAYS
FOUGHT.
WE MUST.
WE ARE HUNTERS,
CAPTAIN,
TRACKING AND TAKING
WHAT WE NEED.
THERE ARE POOR PLANETS
IN THE KLINGON SYSTEMS.
WE MUST PUSH OUTWARD
IF WE ARE TO SURVIVE.
THERE'S ANOTHER WAY
TO SURVIVE--
MUTUAL TRUST
AND HELP.
I WILL HELP YOU NOW.
HOW?
I WILL TAKE YOU TO KANG.
I WILL ADD MY VOICE
TO YOURS.
I WOULDN'T TRUST HER,
CAPTAIN.
WE CAN'T GET THROUGH
THE KLINGON DEFENSES
IN TIME
UNLESS...
SPOCK.
INTRASHIP BEAMING.
FROM ONE SECTION
TO ANOTHER,
IT'S POSSIBLE?
IT HAS RARELY BEEN DONE
BECAUSE OF THE DANGER
INVOLVED.
PINPOINT ACCURACY
IS REQUIRED.
IF THE TRANSPORTEE
SHOULD MATERIALIZE
INSIDE A SOLID OBJECT,
A DECK OR A WALL--
EVEN IF
IT COULD WORK,
SHE MAY BE
LEADING YOU
INTO A TRAP.
WE'RE ALL IN A TRAP.
THIS IS THE ONLY
WAY OUT.
WE'LL GO
WITH YOU.
NO. IT'LL START
THE FINAL BATTLE.
I BELIEVE HER.
PREPARE THE TRANSPORTER.
WE'LL WAIT FOR YOUR SIGNAL.
BUT SHE CAN'T GUARANTEE
THAT KANG WILL STOP
TO LISTEN,
RIGHT, MR. SPOCK?
NO ONE CAN GUARANTEE
THE ACTIONS OF ANOTHER.
YOUR AUTOMATIC SETTING
IS LAID IN, CAPTAIN.
WHEN TRANSPORTER
IS ENERGIZED,
YOU'LL HAVE 8 SECONDS
TO GET TO THE PADS.
I HOPE YOUR COMPUTATIONS
ARE CORRECT, MR. SPOCK.
YOU'LL KNOW IN
7.9 SECONDS,
CAPTAIN.
MARA, YOU'RE ALIVE.
AND YOU BRING US
A PRIZE.
KANG, WAIT.
HE'S COME ALONE,
UNARMED.
HE MUST TALK TO YOU.
BRAVE CAPTAIN,
WHAT ABOUT?
NO!
LISTEN TO HIM.
WE ARE ALL
IN DANGER.
MARA. BEFORE
YOU START KILLING,
GIVE ME ONE MINUTE.
KANG, DON'T!
WHAT HAVE THEY DONE
TO YOU, MARA?
ARE YOU OUT OF YOUR MIND?
WHAT HAVE THEY DONE
TO YOU?
I SEE WHY THE HUMAN BEAST
DID NOT KILL YOU.
THEY DIDN'T HARM ME.
LISTEN TO HIM.
STOP!
STOP, PLEASE!
WITH YOUR DEATH,
WE WIN.
NOBODY WINS.
HAVE ANY MORE OF
YOUR MEN DIED?
WE CAN'T BE KILLED.
THERE'S AN ALIEN ABOARD.
IT WANTS US ALIVE.
NO DOUBT
YOU WILL REASSEMBLE
AFTER I HAVE HACKED
YOU TO BITS!
YOU FOOL.
LOOK!
KANG, FOR THE REST
OF OUR LIVES--
A THOUSAND LIFETIMES--
SENSELESS VIOLENCE,
FIGHTING,
WHILE A-AN ALIEN
HAS TOTAL CONTROL
OVER US.
ALL RIGHT.
IN THE HEART.
IN THE HEAD.
I WON'T STAY DEAD.
NEXT TIME I'LL DO
THE SAME TO YOU.
I'LL KILL YOU.
AND IT GOES ON AND ON,
THE GOOD OLD GAME
OF WAR,
PAWN AGAINST PAWN!
STOPPING THE BAD GUYS.
WHILE SOMEWHERE
SOME...THING
SITS BACK AND LAUGHS...
AND STARTS IT
ALL OVER AGAIN.
LET'S JUMP HIM.
THOSE WHO HATE
AND FIGHT
MUST STOP
THEMSELVES, DOCTOR.
OTHERWISE, IT IS
NOT STOPPED.
KANG, I AM YOUR WIFE.
I'M A KLINGON.
WOULD I LIE FOR THEM?
LISTEN TO KIRK.
HE IS TELLING THE TRUTH.
BE A PAWN, BE A TOY,
BE A GOOD SOLDIER THAT
NEVER QUESTIONS ORDERS.
KLINGONS KILL
FOR THEIR OWN PURPOSES.
ALL FIGHTING MUST END,
CAPTAIN,
TO WEAKEN THE ALIEN
BEFORE OUR DILITHIUM
CRYSTALS ARE GONE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
Uhura: YES, CAPTAIN?
PUT ME ON SHIPWIDE
INTERCOM.
Uhura: AYE, SIR.
KANG.
Uhura: READY, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KIRK.
A TRUCE IS ORDERED.
THE FIGHTING IS OVER.
LAY DOWN YOUR WEAPONS.
THIS IS KANG.
CEASE HOSTILITIES.
DISARM.
THE CESSATION
OF VIOLENCE
APPEARS TO HAVE
WEAKENED IT,
CAPTAIN.
I SUGGEST
THAT GOOD SPIRITS
MIGHT MAKE
AN EFFECTIVE WEAPON.
GET OFF MY SHIP!
YOU'RE A DEAD DUCK HERE.
YOU'RE POWERLESS.
WE KNOW ABOUT YOU.
AND WE DON'T
WANT TO PLAY.
MAYBE...
MAYBE THERE ARE OTHERS
LIKE YOU AROUND.
MAYBE YOU'VE CAUSED
A LOT OF SUFFERING,
A LOT OF HISTORY,
BUT THAT'S ALL OVER.
WE'LL BE ON GUARD NOW,
WE'LL BE READY FOR YOU,
SO SHIP OUT!
COME ON! HAUL IT!
YEAH, OUT ALREADY.
[KIRK AND McCOY LAUGH]
OUT!
WE NEED NO URGING
TO HATE HUMANS.
BUT, FOR THE PRESENT,
ONLY A FOOL FIGHTS
IN A BURNING HOUSE.
OUT!
[ALL LAUGH]