[ALARM]
DO WE HAVE MAXIMUM
MAGNIFICATION, LIEUTENANT?
YES, SIR.
MISSILE SPREAD,
MR. SPOCK.
VERY ARCHAIC TYPE,
CAPTAIN.
SUBLIGHT SPEED.
AYE, AND CHEMICALLY
FUELED TO BOOT, SIR.
ANYTHING ON COMMUNICATION,
LIEUTENANT UHURA?
NO, SIR.
ALL BANDS CLEAR.
COURSE OF THE MISSILE,
MR. SPOCK?
IT WOULD APPEAR
THAT THE ENTERPRISE
IS THE TARGET, CAPTAIN.
PREPARE PHASER BANKS
ONE AND TWO,
MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, GET A FIX
ON THE MISSILE'S
POINT OF ORIGIN.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
PHASERS ONE AND TWO
LOCKED IN AND READY,
SIR.
FIRE PHASERS.
MR. CHEKOV,
ALTER COURSE
TO THE MISSILE'S
POINT OF ORIGIN.
AYE, SIR.
WARP FACTOR THREE,
MR. SULU.
WARP FACTOR
THREE, SIR.
I AM
A NURSE FIRST,
DR. McCOY,
AND A MEMBER
OF THE CREW
OF THE ENTERPRISE,
SECOND.
YOU'RE EXCUSED.
YOU MAY RETURN
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
NO, I'M SORRY,
DOCTOR.
I HAVE CALLED
THE CAPTAIN,
AND I'LL WAIT
UNTIL HE COMES.
WHAT'S THE EMERGENCY?
I SAID YOU
WERE EXCUSED, NURSE.
PLEASE, CHRISTINE.
I PROMISE YOU
I'LL GIVE
THE CAPTAIN
A FULL REPORT.
THAT WAS QUITE A SCENE.
I'VE JUST COMPLETED
THE STANDARD
PHYSICAL EXAMINATIONS
FOR THE ENTIRE CREW.
EXCELLENT.
WHAT'S THE EMERGENCY?
THE CREW IS FIT.
I FOUND
NOTHING UNUSUAL
WITH ONE EXCEPTION.
SERIOUS?
TERMINAL.
WHAT IS IT?
XENOPOLYCYTHEMIA.
IT HAS NO CURE.
WHO?
HE HAS ONE YEAR
TO LIVE AT THE MOST.
WHO IS IT?
THE SHIP'S CHIEF
MEDICAL OFFICER.
YOU.
I'LL BE MOST
EFFECTIVE ON THE JOB
IN THE TIME LEFT
IF YOU'LL KEEP THIS
TO YOURSELF.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STAR DATE 5476.3.
I HAVE JUST HAD
THE SAD DUTY
OF INFORMING STARFLEET
ABOUT DR. McCOY'S CONDITION
AND HAVE REQUESTED
AN IMMEDIATE REPLACEMENT.
MR. SPOCK.
YES, CAPTAIN?
CONFIRM
CHEKOV'S COORDINATES
FOR THE MISSILE'S
POINT OF ORIGIN.
CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE APPROACHING
THOSE COORDINATES.
AND THAT OBJECT
ON THE SCREEN?
AN ASTEROID.
200 MILES
IN DIAMETER.
COULD THE ENEMY
VESSEL BE HIDING
BEHIND THE ASTEROID?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE HAD THAT AREA
ON SCANNERS CONSTANTLY.
THEN THE ASTEROID
IS THE MISSILE'S
POINT OF ORIGIN.
CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
FULL SENSOR PROBE,
MR. SPOCK.
TYPICAL ASTEROID
CHEMICALLY,
BUT IT IS NOT ORBITING.
IT IS PURSING
AN INDEPENDENT COURSE
THROUGH THIS SOLAR SYSTEM.
HOW CAN THAT BE?
UNLESS IT'S POWERED,
A SPACESHIP.
IT IS UNDER POWER,
CAPTAIN.
AND CORRECTING FOR ALL
GRAVITATIONAL STRESSES.
SOURCE OF POWER.
ATOMIC,
VERY ARCHAIC,
LEAVING A TRAIL
OF DEBRIS
AND HARD RADIATION.
MR. CHEKOV,
PLOT THE COURSE
OF THE ASTEROID VESSEL.
AYE, SIR.
ASTEROID HAS
AN OUTER SHELL,
WHICH IS HOLLOW.
IT SURROUNDS
AN INDEPENDENT
INNER CORE,
WHICH HAS A BREATHABLE
ATMOSPHERE.
SENSORS READ
NO LIFE FORMS.
THEN IT MUST BE
ON AUTOMATIC CONTROLS.
AND THE PASSENGERS
OR BUILDERS ARE DEAD.
COURSE OF ASTEROID--
I MEAN, SPACESHIP--
241 MARK 17.
INTERESTING.
YES.
THE COURSE ENSIGN CHEKOV
JUST GAVE FOR THE ASTEROID
WOULD PUT IT ON
A COLLISION COURSE
WITH DARAN FIVE.
DARAN FIVE?
INHABITED?
CORRECT.
POPULATION APPROXIMATELY
3,724,000,000
IF MEMORY SERVES
ME CORRECTLY.
ESTIMATED TIME
OF IMPACT 396 DAYS.
MR. SULU,
MATCH ENTERPRISE SPEED
WITH THAT
OF THE ASTEROID VESSEL.
MR. SPOCK AND I
ARE TRANSPORTING ABOARD.
MR. SCOTT,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
AYE, SIR.
A LOT CAN HAPPEN
IN A YEAR.
PLEASE, GIVE YOURSELF
EVERY MINUTE.
DR. McCOY,
MR. SPOCK AND I
WILL HANDLE THIS.
WITHOUT ME, JIM?
YOU'D NEVER FIND
YOUR WAY BACK.
WELL...
I THINK IT WOULD
BE WISER IF--
I'D LIKE TO GO.
I'M FINE,
CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR.
IF THAT'S
WHAT YOU WANT.
McCoy: YOU'D SWEAR
YOU'RE ON THE SURFACE
OF A PLANET.
Spock: ONE FAILS
TO SEE THE LOGIC
IN MAKING A SHIP
LOOK LIKE A PLANET.
Kirk: WOULDN'T KNOW
THIS WAS A SPACESHIP.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT HERE.
TRANSPORT WITHOUT INCIDENT.
KIRK OUT.
NO APPARENT OPENING.
YOU FOUND NO INTELLIGENT
LIFE FORMS, MR. SPOCK,
BUT SURELY--
THE ASTEROID SHIP IS
OVER 10,000 YEARS OLD
DOCTOR.
STILL NO SIGN
OF LIFE FORMS, CAPTAIN.
THESE ARE WEAPONS.
OF A SORT.
WEAPONS.
COMMUNICATION DEVICES.
LET ME GO
TO MY FRIEND.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I THINK SO.
I AM NATIRA,
THE HIGH PRIESTESS
OF THE PEOPLE.
WELCOME TO THE WORLD
OF YONADA.
I CAN'T SAY
I THINK MUCH
OF YOUR WELCOME.
TAKE THEM.
YOU WILL KNEEL.
SHE CALLED THIS
THE WORLD.
THESE PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
THEY'RE ON A SPACESHIP.
THEY'VE BEEN IN FLIGHT
10,000 YEARS.
Maybe they don't
realize it.
OH, ORACLE
OF THE PEOPLE,
MOST PERFECT AND WISE,
STRANGERS HAVE COME
TO OUR WORLD.
THEY BEAR INSTRUMENTS
WE DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM CAPTAIN KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE.
THIS IS MY MEDICAL OFFICER,
DR. McCOY.
MY FIRST OFFICER,
MR. SPOCK.
FOR WHAT REASON
DO YOU VISIT THIS WORLD?
WE COME IN FRIENDSHIP.
[THUNDER]
THEN LEARN WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE OUR ENEMY
BEFORE YOU LEARN
WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE OUR FRIEND.
SPOCK?
DR. McCOY.
BONES?
BONES.
THE DOCTOR MUST'VE RECEIVED
AN EXCESSIVELY LARGE
ELECTRICAL SHOCK.
NO, THAT'S NOT IT.
NOTHING ELSE COULD'VE
CAUSED THIS, CAPTAIN...
AT LEAST NOTHING
THAT HAS HAPPENED HERE.
YOU'RE RIGHT, SPOCK.
THE SHOCK IS SERIOUS
BECAUSE OF McCOY'S
WEAKENED CONDITION.
MAY I ASK...
PRECISELY WHAT IS
TROUBLING THE DOCTOR?
I DON'T THINK
HE WOULD'VE
TOLD YOU HIMSELF,
BUT I THINK
YOU SHOULD KNOW NOW.
IT'S XENOPOLYCYTHEMIA.
YES.
I KNOW OF IT, CAPTAIN.
THEN YOU KNOW
THAT NOTHING CAN BE DONE.
MMM.
BONES.
HOW IS IT?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK?
VERY WELL, DOCTOR.
THE CAPTAIN AND I
SEEM TO HAVE SUFFERED
NO ILL EFFECTS.
OH, THAT ORACLE
REALLY GOT TO ME.
I MUST BE ESPECIALLY
SUSCEPTIBLE
TO ITS MAGIC SPELLS.
SPOCK KNOWS.
WELL, WE BETTER GET
TO THE CONTROL ROOM.
ARE YOU IN ANY CONDITION
TO GET UP?
DON'T WORRY.
I CAN MAKE IT,
JIM.
CAPTAIN, INFORMING
THESE PEOPLE
THEY'RE ON A SHIP
MAY BE IN VIOLATION
OF THE PRIME DIRECTIVE
OF STARFLEET COMMAND.
NO. THE PEOPLE OF YONADA
MAY BE CHANGED
BY THE KNOWLEDGE,
BUT IT'S BETTER
THAN EXTERMINATING THEM.
LOGICAL, CAPTAIN.
AND THE THREE BILLION
ON DARAN FIVE.
ALSO LOGICAL,
CAPTAIN.
GENTLEMEN, I BELIEVE
WE HAVE A VISITOR.
FOR STRENGTH.
MANY OF US HAVE FELT
THE POWER
OF OUR ORACLE.
THIS HAS BEEN
OF BENEFIT.
TASTES LIKE
AN ANCIENT HERB
DERIVATIVE.
YOU ARE...
NOT OF YONADA.
NO, WE'RE FROM
OUTSIDE YOUR WORLD.
WHERE IS OUTSIDE?
UP THERE.
OUTSIDE, UP THERE,
EVERYWHERE.
SO THEY SAY, ALSO.
MANY YEARS AGO...
I CLIMBED THE MOUNTAINS,
EVEN THOUGH
IT IS FORBIDDEN.
WHY IS IT FORBIDDEN?
I AM NOT SURE.
BUT THINGS...
ARE NOT...
AS THEY TEACH US.
FOR THE WORLD
IS HOLLOW,
AND I...HAVE
TOUCHED THE SKY.
AAH!
WHAT IS IT, BONES?
THERE'S SOMETHING
UNDER THE SKIN.
HE'S DEAD.
"FOR THE WORLD
IS HOLLOW,
AND I HAVE TOUCHED
THE SKY."
HE SAID IT WAS FORBIDDEN
TO CLIMB THE MOUNTAINS.
YES, OF COURSE IT IS,
BECAUSE IF YOU DID,
YOU'D TOUCH THE SKY
AND FIND OUT
THAT YOU WERE LIVING
ON A BIG BALL,
NOT A PLANET,
BUT A SPACESHIP.
AND THAT KNOWLEDGE SEEMS
TO BE FORBIDDEN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE DON'T KNOW.
HE JUST SUDDENLY SCREAMED
IN PAIN AND DIED.
FETCH THE GUARD.
FORGIVE HIM,
FOR HE WAS
AN OLD MAN,
AND OLD MEN ARE
SOMETIMES FOOLISH.
BUT IT IS WRITTEN
THAT THOSE
OF THE PEOPLE
WHO SIN
OR SPEAK EVIL
SHALL BE PUNISHED.
HE SERVED WELL
FOR MANY YEARS.
TAKE HIM AWAY GENTLY.
YOU DO NOT SEEM WELL.
IT IS DISTRESSING
TO ME.
OH, NO.
I'M QUITE ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
IT IS THE WILL
OF THE ORACLE
THAT YOU NOW
BE TREATED
AS HONORED GUESTS.
YOU SEEM TO BE
THE SPECIAL FAVORITE.
INDEED, DOCTOR.
THE YOUNG LADY DID SHOW
A MARKED PREFERENCE
FOR YOUR COMPANY.
WELL, NOW NOBODY CAN
BLAME HER FOR THAT,
CAN THEY?
PERSONALLY, I FIND
THE LADY'S TASTE
QUESTIONABLE,
BUT SHE OBVIOUSLY
PREFERS YOU,
AND YOU OBVIOUSLY
DON'T SEEM TO MIND.
IF YOU COULD ARRANGE
TO BE ALONE
WITH THE YOUNG LADY,
SPOCK AND I
WOULD BE LEFT ALONE
TO FIND THE POWER CONTROLS
OF THIS WORLD.
IT IS TIME
TO REFRESH
YOURSELVES.
THANK YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
TO OUR GOOD FRIENDS
OF YONADA.
WE ARE VERY INTERESTED
IN YOUR WORLD.
THAT PLEASES US.
GOOD. THEN YOU
WOULDN'T MIND IF WE
LOOKED AROUND.
NOT AT ALL.
THE PEOPLE KNOW
OF YOU NOW.
[COUGHING]
ARE YOU WELL ENOUGH
TO GO ABOUT?
PERHAPS NOT.
THEN WHY NOT
REMAIN HERE?
REST.
WE WILL TALK.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
YOU ARE FREE TO GO ABOUT
AND MEET OUR PEOPLE.
THANK YOU.
AND THANK YOU
FOR TAKING CARE
OF DR. McCOY.
NOT AT ALL.
WE SHALL MAKE HIM WELL.
MR. SPOCK.
NO, THANK YOU.
LEAVE US.
I'M CURIOUS.
HOW DID THE ORACLE
PUNISH THE OLD MAN?
I...
CANNOT TELL YOU NOW.
THERE IS SOME WAY
THE ORACLE KNOWS
WHAT YOU SAY,
ISN'T THERE?
WHAT WE SAY.
WHAT WE THINK.
THE ORACLE KNOWS
THE MINDS AND THE HEARTS
OF ALL THE PEOPLE.
I DID NOT KNOW
YOU WOULD BE HURT
SO BADLY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I SUPPOSE WE HAD
TO LEARN THE POWER
OF THE ORACLE.
McCOY, THERE IS
SOMETHING I MUST SAY.
SINCE THE MOMENT I...
IT IS NOT IN THE MANNER
OF THE PEOPLE TO HIDE
THEIR FEELINGS.
OH. HONESTY
IS USUALLY WISE.
IS THERE A WOMAN
FOR YOU?
NO, THERE ISN'T.
DOES McCOY
FIND ME ATTRACTIVE?
OH, YES.
YES, I DO.
I HOPE YOU MEN OF SPACE,
OF OTHER WORLDS,
HOLD TRUTH
AS DEAR AS WE DO.
WE DO.
I WISH YOU TO STAY HERE...
ON YONADA...
AS MY MATE.
BUT WE'RE STRANGERS
TO EACH OTHER.
BUT IS NOT THAT THE NATURE
OF MEN AND WOMEN...
THAT THE PLEASURE
IS IN THE LEARNING
OF EACH OTHER?
YES.
LET THE THOUGHT REST
IN YOUR HEART, McCOY.
INCREDIBLE
AS IT MAY SEEM,
THESE PEOPLE HAVE
NO IDEA THEY'RE
LIVING ON A SPACESHIP.
I WONDER HOW MANY
GENERATIONS HAVE
LIVED OUT THEIR LIVES
AND BEEN BURIED HERE
WITHOUT EVER KNOWING
THAT THEIR WORLD IS HOLLOW.
THE PEOPLE
IN THE FULLNESS OF TIME
WILL REACH A NEW WORLD--
RICH, GREEN,
LOVELY TO THE EYES,
AND OF A GOODNESS
THAT WILL FILL THE HEARTS
OF THE PEOPLE
WITH TEARS OF JOY.
YOU CAN SHARE
THAT WORLD WITH ME,
RULE IT BY MY SIDE.
HOW LONG WILL IT
TAKE YOU TO REACH
THIS NEW WORLD?
SOON. THE ORACLE
WILL ONLY SAY SOON.
OH, IF YOU ONLY KNEW
HOW I NEEDED SOME KIND
OF FUTURE, NATIRA.
YOU HAVE LIVED
A LONELY LIFE?
YES. VERY LONELY.
NO MORE, McCOY.
THERE WILL BE NO MORE
LONELINESS FOR YOU.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I NEED TO TELL YOU.
THERE IS NOTHING
YOU NEED TO SAY.
BUT THERE IS.
THEN TELL ME...
IF THE TELLING
IS SUCH A NEED.
I HAVE AN ILLNESS
FOR WHICH THERE IS
NO CURE.
I HAVE ONE YEAR TO LIVE.
UNTIL I SAW YOU,
THERE WAS NOTHING
IN MY HEART.
IT SUSTAINED MY LIFE,
BUT NOTHING MORE.
NOW IT SINGS.
I COULD BE HAPPY
TO HAVE THAT FEELING
FOR A DAY...
A WEEK, A MONTH...
A YEAR...
WHATEVER
THE CREATORS HOLD
IN STORE FOR US.
CAPTAIN,
THE ORACLE ROOM.
THE PROBLEM--
TO GET IN.
I BELIEVE THAT I CAN...
THE WRITING IS DEFINITELY
FABRINI, CAPTAIN.
I RECOGNIZE IT.
FABRINI.
DIDN'T THE FABRINI SUN
GO NOVA AND DESTROY
ITS PLANETS?
YES. TOWARD THE END,
THE FABRINI PEOPLE
LIVED UNDERGROUND,
AS THESE PEOPLE DO,
TO PROTECT THEMSELVES.
SOME OF THEM
MUST HAVE BEEN PUT
ABOARD THIS SHIP
AND SENT
TO ANOTHER PLANET,
AND THESE ARE
THEIR DESCENDANTS.
NOW.
THE ORACLE DOESN'T SEEM
TO KNOW WE'RE HERE.
I WONDER WHAT ALERTED IT
THE FIRST TIME.
CAPTAIN.
IF I
REMEMBER CORRECTLY,
THE ORACLE'S
REPREHENSIBLE
CONDUCT
WAS INITIATED
WHEN NATIRA KNELT
ON THAT PLATFORM.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
CONTINUE INVESTIGATING.
THE CLUE TO THE LOCATION
OF THE CONTROL ROOM
MUST BE AROUND HERE
SOMEWHERE.
NOTHING HERE
WHICH WOULD INDICATE
THIS IS ANYTHING
BUT A PLANET.
THERE'S NO QUESTION
BUT THAT THE CREATORS
WOULD BE
CONSIDERED GODS.
THIS PLAQUE
IS A REPRESENTATION
OF A STAR
AND ITS SOLAR SYSTEM.
EIGHT PLANETS, CAPTAIN.
THAT IS THE NUMBER
IN THE FABRINA
SOLAR SYSTEM.
THEN THESE PEOPLE
ARE THE DESCENDANTS
OF THE FABRINI.
NONE, NO DOUBT
THAT THEY'VE BEEN
IN FLIGHT
ON THIS ASTEROID SHIP
FOR 10,000 YEARS.
[DOOR OPENS]
SPEAK.
IT IS I--NATIRA.
YES, NATIRA.
IT IS WRITTEN
THAT ONLY THE HIGH PRIESTESS
OF THE PEOPLE
MAY SELECT HER MATE.
IT IS SO WRITTEN.
THE STRANGERS AMONG US--
THE THREE VISITORS--
THERE IS ONE CALLED McCOY.
I WISH HIM TO REMAIN HERE...
AS MY MATE.
DOES HE
AGREE TO THIS?
I HAVE ASKED HIM.
HE HAS NOT YET
GIVEN ME HIS ANSWER.
HE MUST BECOME
ONE OF THE PEOPLE,
WORSHIP
THE CREATORS,
AND AGREE
TO THE INSERTION
OF THE INSTRUMENT
OF OBEDIENCE.
HE WILL BE TOLD
WHAT MUST BE DONE.
IF HE AGREES
TO ALL THINGS,
IT IS PERMITTED.
TEACH HIM OUR LAWS
CAREFULLY
SO HE COMMITS
NO SACRILEGE,
NO OFFENSE
AGAINST THE PEOPLE
OR THE CREATORS.
IT WILL BE DONE...
OH, MOST WISE.
WHO ARE
THE INTRUDERS?
TWO OF THE STRANGERS--
KIRK AND SPOCK.
McCOY IS NOT
WITH THEM?
NO.
KIRK AND SPOCK
HAVE COMMITTED
SACRILEGE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
MUST BE DONE.
I KNOW.
WHEN THE ORACLE
RELEASES THEM,
TAKE THEM.
FOOLS. YOU THINK
WE ARE CHILDREN?
YOU THINK YOU CAN
DO AS YOU PLEASE,
COMMIT WHATEVER
OFFENSE AMUSES YOU?
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO TO MY FRIENDS?
THEY ENTERED
THE ORACLE ROOM.
AND THE PUNISHMENT
IS DEATH?
YES. I CAN MAKE
NO OTHER DECISION.
WE GAVE THEM OUR TRUST,
THEY BETRAYED US.
THEY ACTED OUT
OF IGNORANCE,
NATIRA.
THEY SAID THEY CAME
IN FRIENDSHIP.
PLEASE. LET THEM
RETURN TO THE SHIP.
I CANNOT.
FOR ME?
I'VE
MADE MY DECISION.
I'M STAYING HERE
ON YONADA.
NATIRA,
WHAT THEY DID,
THEY DID
BECAUSE THEY FELT
THEY HAD TO.
PLEASE LET THEM
RETURN TO THE SHIP.
YOU WON'T REGRET IT.
HOW DO YOU THINK
I'D FEEL IF
I STAYED HERE
WITH THE CHANCE
TO BE HAPPY
FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN MY LIFE
BUT KNOWING
MY FRIENDS HAD DIED?
YES.
SO BE IT.
THIS I WILL DO FOR McCOY.
FOR OUR HAPPINESS
AND FUTURE.
YOU'RE RETURNING WITH US?
NO, I'M NOT.
BONES, THIS ISN'T
A PLANET.
IT'S A SPACESHIP
ON A COLLISION COURSE
WITH DARAN FIVE.
I'M ON A KIND OF
COLLISION COURSE
MYSELF, JIM.
DR. McCOY, I ORDER YOU
TO RETURN WITH US.
AND I REFUSE.
BONES, IF WE CAN'T
CORRECT THE COURSE
OF THIS...SHIP...
WE'LL HAVE TO BLAST IT
OUT OF SPACE.
I INTEND TO STAY
ON THIS SHIP
WITH THESE PEOPLE
WHATEVER HAPPENS.
YOUR DECISION IS
MOST ILLOGICAL,
DOCTOR.
IS IT, MR. SPOCK?
IS IT REALLY?
NATIRA'S ASKED ME TO STAY,
AND I'M STAYING.
AS HER HUSBAND?
YES.
IS THAT TOO MUCH
TO ASK, JIM?
[COMMUNICATOR SIGNALS]
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE BEAMING OVER.
LOCK IN ON OUR SIGNAL.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
AND TRANSPORT MR. SPOCK
AND MYSELF IMMEDIATELY.
BUT, CAPTAIN,
WHAT ABOUT DR. McCOY?
HE'S STAYING, SCOTTY.
KIRK OUT.
TO BECOME ONE OF
THE PEOPLE OF YONADA,
THE INSTRUMENT
OF OBEDIENCE
MUST BE MADE
PART OF YOUR FLESH.
DO YOU NOW
GIVE YOUR CONSENT?
I DO.
PROCEED.
SAY NOW,
BECAUSE ONCE DONE,
IT IS DONE.
LET IT BE DONE.
YOU ARE NOW ONE
WITH MY PEOPLE.
MAY I GIVE YOU
THE LOVE YOU WANT
AND MAKE THE TIME
YOU HAVE BEAUTIFUL.
WE'RE NOW OF ONE MIND.
ONE HEART.
ONE LIFE.
IT IS DONE,
OH, MOST WISE,
OUR LIVING LINK
WITH THE CREATORS.
TEACH HIM, THEN,
WHAT HE MUST KNOW
AS ONE OF THE PEOPLE.
THIS IS THE BOOK
OF THE PEOPLE,
TO BE OPENED AND READ
WHEN WE REACH
THE NEW WORLD
OF THE PROMISE.
IT WAS GIVEN
BY THE CREATORS.
DO THE PEOPLE
KNOW THE CONTENTS
OF THEIR BOOK?
ONLY THAT IT TELLS
OF OUR WORLD HERE
AND WHY SOON ONE DAY
WE MUST LEAVE IT
FOR THE NEW WORLD.
HAS THE REASON
THAT THE PEOPLE
MUST LEAVE HERE
BEEN
REVEALED TO YOU?
NO, IT HAS NOT.
DON'T YOU LONG
TO KNOW ITS SECRETS?
NO. IT IS ENOUGH
FOR ME TO KNOW
THAT WE SHALL
UNDERSTAND ALL
WHEN WE REACH OUR HOME.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 5476.4.
WE ARE ON A PARALLEL
COURSE WITH YONADA.
IT IS STILL ON
A COLLISION COURSE
WITH DARAN FIVE.
OUR FAILURE
TO CORRECT ITS COURSE
AND THE CRITICAL NATURE
OF DR. McCOY'S ILLNESS
MADE THE
EXTRAORDINARY EVENT
OF CONTACT WITH STARFLEET
COMMAND IMPERATIVE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I SYMPATHIZE WITH
YOUR WISH TO STAY,
BUT I HOPE YOU
RECOGNIZE THE NECESSITY
THAT YOU CONTINUE
YOUR MISSION AT ONCE.
THAT IS THE PROBLEM, SIR.
PERHAPS I HAVEN'T
MADE MYSELF CLEAR.
LET ME RESTATE IT.
YOU HAVE BEEN RELIEVED
OF ALL RESPONSIBILITY
FOR THE ASTEROID SHIP
YONADA.
STARFLEET COMMAND WILL
TAKE CARE OF THE SITUATION.
I BELIEVE
IT IS TIME TO MOVE ON.
YES. THOSE ARE THE ORDERS.
[INTERCOM SIGNALS]
CAPTAIN KIRK.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
AN URGENT CALL
FROM DR. McCOY, SIR.
PUT HIM ON.
JIM.
YES, BONES.
WE MAY BE
ABLE TO GET
THESE PEOPLE
BACK ON COURSE.
YOU'VE LOCATED
THE CONTROLS?
NO, BUT I'VE
SEEN THE BOOK
THAT CONTAINS
ALL THE KNOWLEDGE
OF THE CREATORS.
AND IF YOU--
IF YOU CAN GET TO IT...
SPOCK CAN...
DIG OUT THE INFORMATION.
WHERE IS IT?
AAH!
BONES,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
BONES, ANSWER ME!
BONES, WHAT IS IT?
McCOY, WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT'S HAPPENING, McCOY?
YOU ARE KILLERS
OF YOUR FRIEND.
I WILL HAVE YOU
PUT TO DEATH.
HELP HIM.
UNTIL YOU ARE DEAD,
HE WILL THINK OF YOU
AND DISOBEY!
I WILL SEE YOU DIE!
SPOCK, TAKE CARE
OF McCOY.
OH...
HE IS NOT
PART OF OUR PEOPLE.
YOU'VE RELEASED HIM
FROM HIS VOW OF OBEDIENCE.
WE HAVE FREED HIM
FROM THE CRUELTY
OF YOUR ORACLE.
OH...
[GASP]
BONES.
YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT A BOOK.
WHERE IS IT?
THEY MUST NOT KNOW.
THE...ORACLE ROOM.
YOU WILL NEVER
SEE THE BOOK.
IT IS SACRILEGE!
GUARDS!
GUARDS! GUARDS!
NOW
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU MUST LISTEN
TO WHAT I HAVE
TO SAY.
GIVE ME ONE MOMENT
TO SPEAK TO YOU.
ONE MOMENT.
NATIRA,
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE
WHAT I'M
ABOUT TO TELL YOU,
YOU CAN CALL THE GUARDS.
WE'LL ACCEPT ANY
PUNISHMENT YOU DECREE.
WHAT DO YOU
WISH TO SAY?
YOU MUST BELIEVE
THAT WHAT I'M ABOUT
TO TELL YOU IS
THE TRUTH.
YOUR TRUTH
OF YOUR WORLD.
YES. MY WORLD
AND YOUR WORLD
OF YONADA.
YOU DO NOT OBEY THE LAW
OF THE CREATORS.
HOW CAN YOU UNDERSTAND
MY WORLD?
I UNDERSTAND.
I UNDERSTAND, NATIRA.
10,000 YEARS AGO,
A SUN WAS DYING
AND WITH IT, ITS WORLD.
IT'S THE WORLD
YOU SEE ON THE PLAQUE
IN THE ROOM
OF THE ORACLE.
THAT IS A WORLD
OF WHICH YONADA
IS PART.
NO.
IT IS THE WORLD
OF YOUR ANCESTORS,
YOUR...CREATORS.
IT NO LONGER EXISTS.
YOU ARE MAD.
NO, I'M NOT.
NOW LISTEN TO ME!
HEAR ME OUT.
WHEN YOUR ANCESTORS
DISCOVERED
THAT THEIR WORLD
WAS DYING...
THEY BUILT A GREAT SHIP
AND CHOSE
THEIR BEST PEOPLE.
THEY WISHED
FOR THEIR RACE TO SURVIVE.
THEY SENT THE SHIP
OUT INTO SPACE.
YOU WISH ME
TO BELIEVE THAT...
YONADA IS A SHIP?
YES.
BUT WE HAVE A SUN.
IT DID NOT DIE,
AND AT NIGHT,
I SEE THE STARS.
NO.
YOU ARE LIVING INSIDE...
A HOLLOW BALL.
YOUR ANCESTORS CREATED IT
TO TAKE YOU ON A JOURNEY
TO A PROMISED NEW PLANET.
WHY SHOULD THE...
WHY SHOULD
THE TRUTH WAIT
FOR YOU
TO COME TO YONADA?
BECAUSE A FLAW DEVELOPED
IN THE CONTROLS.
AND UNLESS WE CORRECT IT,
YONADA WILL KILL
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
AND DESTROY A WORLD
IT DOESN'T EVEN KNOW.
WHY SHOULD THE TRUTH
BE KEPT FROM US?
WHY SHOULD
THE CREATORS
KEEP US IN DARKNESS?
NO. NO.
YOU DO NOT
SPEAK THE TRUTH.
I BELIEVE
ONLY THE ORACLE.
I BELIEVE!
LET US REMOVE
THE INSTRUMENT
OF OBEDIENCE,
THE WAY
WE DID FOR McCOY.
NATIRA.
DO YOU THINK
SHE UNDERSTOOD ME?
SHE EVIDENTLY
UNDERSTOOD SOMETHING.
THERE ARE NO GUARDS
TO DETAIN US.
YOU HAVE LISTENED
TO THE WORDS OF
THE NON-BELIEVERS.
YES. I HAVE LISTENED.
THAT WAS THE FIRST
TRANSGRESSION.
YOU FELT THE PAIN
OF WARNING?
YES, I DID.
WHY DID YOU
LISTEN FURTHER?
THEY SAID
THEY SPOKE THE TRUTH.
THEIR TRUTH.
IS TRUTH
NOT TRUTH FOR ALL?
THE TRUTH OF YONADA
IS YOUR TRUTH.
THERE CAN BE
NO OTHER FOR YOU.
REPENT
YOUR DISOBEDIENCE.
I MUST KNOW
THE TRUTH OF THE WORLD!
YOUR FRIENDS
HAVE TOLD ME
OF YOUR WORLD.
THEY SPOKE THE TRUTH.
I--I BELIEVE YOU.
I BELIEVE.
THE CREATORS
KEPT US IN DARKNESS.
THERE'S
NOTHING I CAN DO.
I BELIEVE WITH
YOU, HUSBAND.
IS SHE ALL RIGHT?
SHE WILL BE.
I'LL STAY HERE WITH HER.
THE BOOK IS
IN THE MONOLITH.
IT IS SACRILEGE
TO THE TEMPLE.
WE DO THIS
FOR THE SURVIVAL
OF THE PEOPLE OF YONADA.
YOU ARE NOT BELIEVERS.
YOU ARE FORBIDDEN
TO GAZE AT THE BOOK.
WE MEAN NO DESECRATION
TO THE FAITH OF YONADA.
WE MUST CONSULT
THE BOOK TO HELP YOU.
IT IS BLASPHEMY.
YOU ARE FORBIDDEN.
THE PUNISHMENT
IS DEATH.
[THUNDER]
TEMPERATURE
111 DEGREES
AND RISING.
McCOY, HOW DO YOU
OPEN THIS THING?
TEMPERATURE
115 DEGREES.
PRESS THE THREE
LOWER PLANETS
ON THE LEFT-HAND SIDE,
SIMULTANEOUSLY.
120 DEGREES.
HERE. THE PLAN
MUST BE IN THERE.
IS IT INDEXED?
YES, IT IS.
HURRY, SPOCK.
IT REFERS TO THE ALTAR.
"APPLY PRESSURE
TO THE CENTER
UNTIL IT OPENS."
LET'S GET HER
OUT OF THE HEAT.
I'VE NEUTRALIZED
THE HEATING ELEMENTS.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT
HERE NOW, JIM.
THE ORACLE CAN
NO LONGER PUNISH US.
YOUR FRIENDS
HAVE PREVENTED IT?
YES.
AND WILL THEY SEND THIS...
THIS SHIP...
AGAIN TO THE LAND
THE CREATORS INTENDED?
YES.
THAT IS GOOD.
ACTIVE AND FUNCTIONAL,
NOT TOO DIFFERENT
FROM THE ENTERPRISE.
THERE SEEMS TO BE
A WEAKNESS IN ONE
OF THE 8 TUBES.
ENOUGH TO TURN IT
OFF COURSE?
YES.
LET ME CHECK
THAT ENGINE.
VERY SIMPLE PROBLEM,
EASY TO CORRECT.
THEN COME.
NO.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
I DO NOT FEAR THE PUNISHMENT
OF DISOBEDIENCE.
WELL, THEN, COME.
WE MUST HURRY
TO JOIN--
NO. I CANNOT GO WITH YOU.
IT IS NOT FEAR.
I UNDERSTAND THE GREAT
PURPOSE OF THE CREATORS.
I SHALL HONOR IT.
YOU INTEND TO STAY
HERE, ON YONADA?
I SHALL STAY WILLINGLY
AND BECAUSE THAT
IS WHAT I MUST DO.
THEN I WON'T
LEAVE YOU.
WILL McCOY STAY
HERE TO DIE?
NO. McCOY WILL NOT
LET GO OF LIFE
IN THE FULLNESS OF YEARS.
NOW MORE THAN EVER,
I WISH TO SEARCH
THROUGH THE UNIVERSE
TO FIND
A CURE FOR MYSELF
AND ALL OTHERS
LIKE ME.
AND I WANT YOU
TO BE WITH ME.
THIS...
IS MY UNIVERSE.
YOU CAME HERE
WITH A GREAT MISSION--
TO SAVE MY PEOPLE.
SHALL I ABANDON THEM?
PERHAPS ONE DAY,
IF IT IS PERMITTED,
YOU WILL FIND
YONADA AGAIN.
I BELIEVE WE CAN ATTEMPT
THE COURSE CORRECTION,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
GOING BACK
TO MARKED HEADINGS.
GUIDANCE CONTROL'S
TAKING OVER.
I BELIEVE
WE CAN ALLOW THIS SHIP
TO GO BACK TO ITS
AUTOMATIC CONTROL.
STEADYING ON COURSE
MARKED IN RED.
CAPTAIN.
INTELLIGENCE FILES.
THEIR BANKS CONTAIN
THE TOTAL KNOWLEDGE
OF THE FABRINI,
READY FOR THE PEOPLE
TO CONSULT
WHEN THEY ARRIVE AT
THEIR DESTINATION.
AND THEY SEEM
TO HAVE AMASSED
A GREAT DEAL OF
MEDICAL KNOWLEDGE.
EXCELLENT, DOCTOR.
THE WHITE CORPUSCLE COUNT
IS BACK TO NORMAL.
OH...
YOUR HEMOGLOBIN COUNT
IS BACK TO NORMAL,
DOCTOR,
WHICH INDICATES
THAT THE FLOW OF OXYGEN
TO EACH CELL
OF YOUR BODY
IS BACK UP TO ITS
ABUNDANTLY ENERGETIC
LEVEL.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK,
FOR BRINGING BACK
THE KNOWLEDGE OF
THE FABRINI.
DR. McCOY,
THE FABRINI DESCENDANTS
ARE SCHEDULED TO DEBARK
ON THEIR PROMISED PLANET
IN APPROXIMATELY 390 DAYS.
I THINK THAT
WE COULD MANAGE
TO BE IN THAT VICINITY
AT THAT TIME,
IF YOU WANTED TO THANK
THE FABRINI PERSONALLY.