Captain Kirk:
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE, 5693.2.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS APPROACHING
THE LAST REPORTED POSITION
OF THE STARSHIP DEFIANT,
WHICH VANISHED WITHOUT TRACE
THREE WEEKS AGO.
WE ARE IN UNSURVEYED
TERRITORY.
CAPTAIN,WE ARE REGISTERING VERY
CURIOUS READINGS
FROM ALL SENSORS.
SPECIFY.
I CANNOT.
ACCORDING TO OUR
INSTRUMENTS,
SPACE ITSELF IS
LITERALLY BREAKING UP.
THERE IS NO
KNOWN PHENOMENON
WHICH WOULD ACCOUNT
FOR THESE READINGS.
WHAT ABOUT
SENSOR FAILURE?
NEGATIVE. I HAVE RUN
A COMPLETE CHECK
ON ALL SYSTEMS.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE LOSING POWER
IN THE WARP ENGINES.
HOW BAD IS IT?
WE CAN BARELY
READ IT,
BUT I DON'T LIKE
THE LOOKS OF IT.
AND I CANNOT
FIND OUT THE CAUSE.
Chekov:
CAPTAIN.
VISUAL DETECTION
OF AN OBJECT DEAD AHEAD.
HOW ABOUT IT, SPOCK?
FASCINATING.
EXPLAIN.
THERE IS VIRTUALLY
NO SENSOR CONTACT.
NO MASS ANALYSIS.
NO TRACE OF RADIATION.
WE SEE IT,
BUT OUR SENSORS INDICATE
IT IS NOT THERE.
THE DEFIANT.
MR. SULU,
IMPULSE ENGINES ONLY,
AND CLOSE TO
TRANSPORTER RANGE.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT, OPEN UP
A HAILING FREQUENCY.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO RAISE THEM, SIR.
THERE IS NO RESPONSE.
JUST WITHIN
TRANSPORTER RANGE, SIR.
GOOD.
MAINTAIN POSITION.
MR. SPOCK, MR. CHEKOV,
COME WITH ME.
DR. McCOY, REPORT
TO THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM IMMEDIATELY.
SCOTTY, YOU HAVE
THE CON.
AYE, SIR.
LOCKED IN ON
THE DEFIANT BRIDGE, SIR.
ENERGIZE.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[WOMAN VOCALIZING]
HAS THERE
EVER BEEN A MUTINY
ON A STARSHIP BEFORE?
ABSOLUTELY NO RECORD
OF SUCH AN OCCURRENCE,
ENSIGN.
JIM.
THE CAPTAIN'S NECK
IS BROKEN.
THE SHIP IS STILL
FUNCTIONING, CAPTAIN.
IT IS LOGICAL
TO ASSUME THE MUTINEERS
ARE SOMEWHERE ABOARD.
USE THE SHIP'S SENSORS
TO LOCATE THEM.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT, HERE, SIR.
PREPARE TO BEAM OVER
A FULL SECURITY SQUAD
ON MY ORDERS.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, THERE'S
NO SIGN OF LIFE
ABOARD THIS VESSEL.
ODD, MR. SPOCK.
VERY ODD.
SPOCK, YOU STAY HERE
WITH ME.
CHEKOV, GET DOWN
TO ENGINEERING
AND LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS.
DR. McCOY, CHECK OUT
THE SICKBAY.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
CANCEL THE SECURITY SQUAD
AND STAND BY
FOR FURTHER INSTRUCTIONS.
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
STANDING BY.
I CAN'T GET
AN ACCURATE FIX
ON THE DEFIANT,
MR. SCOTT,
BUT I KNOW
IT'S DRIFTING
AWAY FROM US.
SHALL I CORRECT
FOR RANGE, SIR?
AYE, I THINK
YOU'RE RIGHT.
KEEP US
WITHIN BEAMING RANGE,
BUT NOT TOO CLOSE.
[BEEP]
CAPTAIN.
REPORT, MR. CHEKOV.
JUST LIKE WHAT I FOUND
IN LIFE SUPPORT.
ALL DEAD.
GET BACK UP HERE.
KIRK TO McCOY.
McCOY HERE.
BONES, CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT THEY ALL DIED OF?
I'D SAY THESE PEOPLE
KILLED EACH OTHER.
THEY WHAT?
YOU HEARD CORRECTLY, JIM.
THESE PEOPLE
KILLED EACH OTHER.
COULD MENTAL DISEASE
HAVE INFECTED ALL
OF THE CREW?
ACCORDING TO
THE SHIP'S LOG,
THE MEDICAL SURGEON
DOWN HERE
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
THE BEST I CAN DO IS
GET ALL THE READINGS
I CAN GET
AND ANALYZE THEM LATER.
WHAT THE DEVIL?
Kirk: BONES, WHAT IS IT?
BONES, WHAT IS IT?
ANSWER ME!
JIM, THIS SHIP
IS DISSOLVING.
MY HAND JUST
PASSED THROUGH
A MAN AND A TABLE.
GET BACK UP HERE
ON THE DOUBLE!
MR. SCOTT,
THE DEFIANT...
IT'S STARTING
TO DISAPPEAR.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM!
TRANSPORTER ROOM,
O'NEIL HERE.
YOU GOT THAT TRANSPORTER
WORKING YET, MISTER?
NO, SIR. NOT YET.
TAKE OVER, MR. SULU. I'LL BE
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, THE DEFIANT'S
SENSORS CORRESPOND
WITH AN EXTREMELY
HIGH DEGREE OF CORRELATION
TO THOSE
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
YOU MEAN, WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE DEFIANT
MIGHT BE HAPPENING
TO THE ENTERPRISE?
AFFIRMATIVE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
MR. SCOTT.
SCOTT HERE.
MR. SCOTT, STAND BY
TO BEAM US BACK.
I CAN'T, SIR.
AT LEAST
NOT ALL AT ONCE.
WHY NOT?
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
EVERYTHING! THAT SHIP
YOU'RE IN IS FADING OUT,
AND IT'S--
WELL, IT'S
RIPPING THE INNARDS
OUT OF THIS ONE.
IT'S JAMMING
OUR TRANSPORTER
FREQUENCIES.
I'VE ONLY GOT
THREE OF THEM
WORKING,
AND I'M NOT SURE
OF THOSE.
ONE OF YOU
HAS GOT TO WAIT.
CHEKOV, McCOY,
PREPARE FOR TRANSPORTATION.
YOU, TOO, SPOCK.
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO REMAIN, CAPTAIN.
I COULD BE
COMPLETING THE DATA.
REQUEST DENIED.
CAPTAIN, THERE
IS A CHANCE---
I KNOW WHAT
THE CHANCES ARE.
MR. SPOCK,
DON'T ARGUE.
GET BACK WITH
THE INFORMATION.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
SCOTTY, ENERGIZE
TRANSPORTER.
AYE.
ENERGIZE.
IT'S GONE.
THE DEFIANT JUST VANISHED.
ANYTHING?
NEGATIVE.
THAT'S IT.
I'VE DONE ALL I CAN.
THERE'S NOTHING OUT THERE TO
GRAB AHOLD OF AND BRING IN.
WHEN THAT SHIP WENT,
IT MUST HAVE TAKEN
THE CAPTAIN WITH IT.
COMPUTER WORKING.
COMPUTE THE NEXT PERIOD
OF SPATIAL INTERPHASE.
NEXT INTERPHASE
2 HOURS, 12 MINUTES.
2 HOURS
AND 12 MINUTES?
WHY, THAT POWER LEAK
HAS UNBALANCED THE SHIP,
AND SHE'S STARTING
TO DRIFT.
I CAN'T HOLD HER
IN PLACE THAT LONG.
WE MUST TRY, MR. SCOTT.
THE FABRIC OF SPACE
IS VERY WEAK HERE.
IF WE DISTURB IT,
THERE WILL BE NO CHANCE
OF RETRIEVING
THE CAPTAIN ALIVE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S SO SPECIAL
ABOUT THIS REGION
OF SPACE.
WELL, PICTURE IT
THIS WAY, MR. CHEKOV.
WE EXIST
IN A UNIVERSE
WHICH COEXISTS
WITH A MULTITUDE
OF OTHERS
IN THE SAME
PHYSICAL SPACE.
AT CERTAIN
BRIEF PERIODS OF TIME,
AN AREA OF THEIR SPACE
OVERLAPS AN AREA OF OURS.
THAT IS A TIME
OF INTERPHASE,
DURING WHICH
WE CAN CONNECT
WITH THE DEFIANT'S
UNIVERSE.
MR. SPOCK?
WE WILL BE ABLE
TO RETRIEVE THE CAPTAIN
AT THAT TIME,
WON'T WE?
YES.
HOWEVER, THE DIMENSIONAL
STRUCTURE OF EACH UNIVERSE
IS TOTALLY DISSIMILAR.
ANY USE OF POWER
DISTURBS IT.
IF WE ARE NOT
EXTREMELY CAREFUL,
WE SHALL LOSE THE CAPTAIN
AND BECOME TRAPPED
OURSELVES.
I SEE.
AND DIE LIKE HIM?
AAH!
[VOICE ECHOES]
CHEKOV!
AAH!
SECURITY GUARDS
TO THE BRIDGE.
AYE, SIR.
WHAT HAPPENED,
MR. SPOCK?
I WAS ATTEMPTING
TO EXPLAIN TO MR. CHEKOV
THE NATURE OF OUR PROBLEMS
IN THIS SITUATION
WHEN HE ATTACKED.
DID ANYONE NOTICE
ANYTHING PECULIAR
IN HIS BEHAVIOR
BEFORE THIS?
I THINK HE HAD
SEVERAL SPASMS
OF PAIN.
DID HE SEEM TO BE
GETTING HYSTERICAL?
DOCTOR, HE SEEMED MORE
ANGRY THAN FRIGHTENED.
HE HAD NO CAUSE
TO BE ANGRY.
TAKE MR. CHEKOV
TO SICKBAY.
PUT HIM
UNDER RESTRAINT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
IS CORRECT.
THERE WAS MURDEROUS FURY
IN CHEKOV--
THE SAME FURY
WHICH WAS EVIDENT
IN THE DEFIANT.
THAT'S WHAT
I WAS AFRAID OF.
WHATEVER IT WAS THAT DROVE
THE CREW OF THE DEFIANT
TO MURDER EACH OTHER
COULD BE COMMUNICABLE.
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU NEED
TO ISOLATE THE CAUSE?
TIME.
OH, AND BY THE WAY,
MR. SPOCK,
I THINK IT MIGHT BE
A WISE PRECAUTION
TO PUT SOME DISTANCE
BETWEEN US
AND THE DEFIANT.
IF WE ARE TO RECOVER
THE CAPTAIN,
WE MUST NOT MOVE.
HOW LONG WILL THAT TAKE?
APPROXIMATELY TWO HOURS
BEFORE THE ATTEMPT
CAN BE MADE.
SPOCK, ARE YOU SURE
THAT JIM IS STILL ALIVE?
IF THE CAPTAIN WAS CAUGHT
IN OUR TRANSPORTER BEAM
WHEN THE DEFIANT
PHASED OUT,
IT IS POSSIBLE
HE WAS SPARED
THE SHOCK OF TRANSITION
AND SURVIVED.
HOWEVER, IF WE ARE
TO RECOVER HIM,
WE MUST CATCH HIM
AT THE PRECISE MOMENT
DURING THE NEXT
INTERPHASE,
OR HE WILL DIE.
NOW, THERE CAN BE
NO MARGIN FOR ERROR.
HIS ENVIRONMENTAL UNIT
CAN PROVIDE
BREATHABLE AIR
FOR NO MORE THAN
3.62 HOURS.
MR. SPOCK,
A VESSEL APPROACHING
ON AN INTERCEPT VECTOR.
STATUS, MR. SULU.
RANGE--200,000 KILOMETERS.
VELOCITY--0.51 "C."
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
SIGNAL RED ALERT.
AYE, SIR.
RED ALERT.
ALL DECKS,
GO TO RED ALERT!
[ALARM SOUNDS]
SECURITY PATROL.
WILL DO.
[SECURITY OFFICERS
OVER P.A. SYSTEM]
SECURITY PATROL.
WILL DO.
THEY'VE STOPPED DEAD, SIR.
RANGE--90,000 KILOMETERS
AND HOLDING.
MR. SPOCK?
I'M RECEIVING
A VISUAL SIGNAL.
TRANSFER TO MAIN VIEWER.
AYE, SIR.
I AM COMMANDER LOSKENE.
YOU ARE TRESPASSING
IN A TERRITORIAL ANNEX
OF THE THOLIAN ASSEMBLY.
YOU MUST LEAVE THIS AREA
IMMEDIATELY.
SPOCK, IN COMMAND
OF THE FEDERATION
STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
COMMANDER, ACCORDING
TO THE FEDERATION,
THIS AREA
IS FREE SPACE.
WE CLAIM THIS TERRITORY
AND ARE PREPARED
TO USE FORCE, IF NECESSARY,
TO PROTECT OUR PROPERTY.
WE'RE NOT INTERESTED
IN YOUR DISPLAY OF FORCE.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS RESPONDING TO
A DISTRESS SIGNAL
FROM ONE OF OUR SHIPS
AND IS CURRENTLY ENGAGED
IN RESCUE OPERATIONS.
DO YOU WISH
TO ASSIST US?
I FIND NO EVIDENCE
OF A DISABLED SHIP.
MY INSTRUMENTS INDICATE
THAT OURS ARE THE ONLY TWO
VESSELS IN THIS AREA.
THE OTHER SHIP IS
INTERSPATIALLY TRAPPED.
IT SHOULD REAPPEAR
IN 1 HOUR AND 53 MINUTES.
WE REQUEST
YOU STAND BY UNTIL THEN.
VERY WELL, ENTERPRISE.
IN THE INTEREST
OF INTERSTELLAR AMITY,
WE WILL WAIT PRECISELY
1 HOUR AND 53 MINUTES,
BUT BE CORRECT.
WE DO NOT TOLERATE
DECEIT.
IF WE COULD ONLY FIND
THE PROPER FILTERING
AGENT,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SOLVE THIS PROBLEM.
NEGATIVE.
IT'S THE THIRD FAILURE.
NURSE, TAKE THIS SAMPLE
AND RUN AN ANALYSIS
ON IT.
YES, DOCTOR.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
TRANSPORTER ROOM HERE.
READY FOR INTERPHASE
IN 20 SECONDS.
DR. McCOY!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
THANK YOU, NURSE.
CALL SECURITY.
I WANT TO HAVE
SOME CHECKS RUN
ON THIS MAN.
LOCK ON TO CAPTAIN KIRK'S
COORDINATES AND PREPARE
TO BRING HIM ABOARD,
MR. SCOTT.
BRING HIM ABOARD,
I'M TRYING.
CAPTAIN KIRK IS NOT
ON HIS DESIGNATED
COORDINATES, MR. SPOCK.
WELL, KEEP TRYING,
MR. SCOTT.
LIEUTENANT SULU,
EVALUATION.
SENSOR READINGS
ARE NOT CORRESPONDING
TO THOSE WE RECEIVED
THE LAST TIME WE SAW
THE DEFIANT.
IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT THOLIAN ENTRY
INTO THE AREA
HAS DISTURBED THE SPACE.
AND IF THAT
HAS OCCURRED...
McCOY TO BRIDGE.
SPOCK HERE.
HAS THE CAPTAIN
BEEN BEAMED ABOARD YET?
NEGATIVE, DOCTOR.
WELL, WHEN IS THAT
INTERPHASE GOING
TO HAPPEN?
THEORETICALLY,
IT ALREADY HAS
HAPPENED, DOCTOR,
HOWEVER, THE SHIP'S SENSORS
ARE NOT RESPONDING
AS PREDICTED.
WELL, I THOUGHT
YOU HAD THE THING
TIMED OUT.
I DID, DOCTOR.
THE SPACE WAS DISTURBED
BY THE THOLIANS.
YOU MEAN, YOU DON'T KNOW
WHETHER YOU'RE GONNA
BE ABLE TO RECOVER
THE CAPTAIN OR NOT?
NOT AT THIS INTERPHASE.
I SHALL HAVE
TO RECALCULATE
TO DETERMINE WHEN
THE NEXT INTERPHASE WILL OCCUR.
THEY DO NOT TAKE PLACE
AT REGULAR INTERVALS.
YOU CAN'T WAIT
FOR THE NEXT ONE.
WE'VE HAD
ANOTHER CASE
LIKE CHEKOV.
I'VE HAD TO CONFINE
MY ORDERLY TO
SICKBAY.
I HAVE CONFIDENCE
THAT YOU WILL SOON
ISOLATE THE CAUSE, DOCTOR,
AND PREVENT ANY FURTHER
SPREAD OF THE AFFLICTION.
THE DISEASE IS NOT
TRANSMITTED BY THE MEN,
MR. SPOCK.
THE CAUSE IS THE AREA
OF SPACE WE'RE IN.
IT'S AFFECTING
THE WHOLE CREW.
THE MOLECULAR STRUCTURE
OF THE BRAIN TISSUES
IN THE CENTRAL
NERVOUS SYSTEM
ARE DISTORTING.
AND THE MADNESS
THAT AFFECTED
THE DEFIANT'S CREW
WILL SOON HAPPEN
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
NOW, YOU'VE GOT
TO GET THIS SHIP
OUT OF HERE!
MR. SPOCK,
WE'RE BEING
FIRED UPON.
THE RENOWNED
THOLIAN PUNCTUALITY.
MR. SPOCK,
DAMAGE CONTROL REPORT--
MINOR STRUCTURAL DAMAGE
TO SECTIONS A-4 AND C-13.
ENGINEERING,
HOLD POWER STEADY
AND CUT OFF ALL
UNNECESSARY EXPENDITURES.
MR. SULU, DIVERT ALL BUT
EMERGENCY MAINTENANCE POWER
TO THE SHIELDS.
BUT SIR, THAT WILL
REDUCE OUR
PHASER POWER BY 50%.
MR. SPOCK!
SCOTT TO BRIDGE!
SPOCK HERE.
I KNOW YOU DON'T LIKE
TO USE THE PHASERS,
BUT YOU'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT
THAT SHIP OUT THERE!
UNDERSTOOD.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN A CHANNEL
TO THE THOLIAN SHIP.
AYE, SIR.
MR. SULU, LOCK IN
PHASER TRACKING CONTROLS.
PHASERS LOCKED IN,
SIR.
THERE'S NO RESPONSE
ON ANY FREQUENCY, SIR.
WHAT'S THE USE OF
THIS BATTLE, SPOCK?
YOU'VE LOST JIM.
TAKE THE SHIP
OUT OF HERE.
READY, MR. SULU?
READY, MR. SPOCK.
FIRE.
A HIT, MR. SPOCK!
ENGINEERING,
STATUS REPORT.
MR. SCOTT--
SPOCK, THAT HIT
WE TOOK FROM THE THOLIANS
HAS FUSED OUR POWER SUPPLY
CONVERTERS.
I CAN'T DO A THING
WITH THE ENTERPRISE NOW.
SHE'S BOUND TO DRIFT,
MAYBE RIGHT THROUGH
THAT DOORWAY OUT THERE.
CAN YOU ESTIMATE
MINIMUM TIME REQUIRED
FOR REPAIR?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF SHE CAN BE REPAIRED.
ARE YOU SATISFIED?
SPOCK,
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
THE DECISION TO FIGHT
WAS LOGICAL.
LACK OF TIME
PREVENTED ANY OTHER
COURSE OF ACTION.
THE THOLIAN SHIP
HAD TO BE DISABLED.
YOU SHOULD'VE KNOWN
WHAT COULD'VE HAPPENED
AND DONE EVERYTHING
IN YOUR POWER
TO SAFEGUARD YOUR CREW.
THAT IS THE MARK OF
A STARSHIP CAPTAIN,
LIKE JIM.
DOCTOR, I HARDLY BELIEVE
THIS IS THE TIME
FOR COMPARISONS.
PLEASE GO AT ONCE
TO YOUR LABORATORY
AND SEARCH FOR AN ANTIDOTE
TO THE EFFECTS
OF THIS SPACE.
THAT IS YOUR PRIMARY TASK,
SINCE WE MUST REMAIN HERE.
MR. SPOCK...
SOMETHING HAS
JUST ENTERED
SENSOR RANGE.
IT'S ANOTHER
THOLIAN, SIR.
LOSKENE MUST'VE
CONTACTED THEM
WHEN HE TRIED
TO INTERCEPT US.
FASCINATING.
SHALL I LOCK IN
REMAINING
PHASER POWER, SIR?
NEGATIVE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CAN YOU OPEN A CHANNEL
TO THE APPROACHING VESSEL?
THEY'RE REFUSING RECEPTION,
SIR. I CAN'T--
DISTANCE, MR. SULU.
JUST BEYOND
PHASER RANGE, SIR.
WHAT IS THAT?
MR. SULU, I SHALL
RUN AN ANALYSIS
ON THOSE FILAMENTS.
TIE IN ALL SENSORS
TO THE SHIP'S LIBRARY
COMPUTER CONSOLE.
SWITCH SCANNERS.
YES, SIR.
THERE'S NO ANALOG
TO THIS STRUCTURE
IN FEDERATION TECHNOLOGY.
IT IS, HOWEVER,
AN ENERGY FIELD,
AND IF THE THOLIANS
ARE SUCCESSFUL
IN COMPLETING THIS STRUCTURE
BEFORE WE HAVE
COMPLETED OUR REPAIRS...
WE SHALL NOT
SEE HOME AGAIN.
DOCTOR,
YOUR LAST REPORT
ON AN ANTIDOTE
ON THE EFFECTS
OF THIS SPACE
WAS NEGATIVE.
IT'S STILL NEGATIVE,
MR. SPOCK.
THARAGEN SEEMS TO BE
THE MOST PROMISING SUBSTANCE
TESTED SO FAR.
WE'RE PROGRESSING.
THE URGENCY REQUIRES
YOUR PERSONAL ATTENTION
IN THE LABORATORY.
MY STAFF IS WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK.
MY BEING THERE WILL NOT
AFFECT THE BIOCHEMISTRY
OF ANY OF THE TESTS.
THIS SERVICE REQUIRES
MY PERSONAL ATTENTION,
MR. SPOCK.
A FEW HOURS AGO,
THE CAPTAIN ELECTED TO
REMAIN ONBOARD THE DEFIANT
SO THAT THREE MEMBERS
OF HIS CREW
WOULD HAVE THE BEST CHANCE
OF RETURNING SAFELY
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
HIS CONCERN
WAS NOT ONLY FOR THEM,
BUT FOR ALL THE MEMBERS
OF THE CREW OF THIS SHIP.
YOU ALL KNOW
THE SEQUENCE OF EVENTS.
YOU WERE FIRED UPON
BY THE THOLIAN SHIP.
AT THAT TIME,
CAPTAIN KIRK
MAY HAVE BEEN ALIVE.
I DEEMED IT NECESSARY
TO RETURN THE THOLIAN FIRE
FOR THE SAFETY
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
THE THOLIAN SHIP
HAS BEEN DISABLED.
BUT AS A RESULT
OF THE BATTLE,
WE MUST ACCEPT THE FACT
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
IS NO LONGER ALIVE.
AAH!
TAKE HIM TO SICKBAY.
PUT HIM IN RESTRAINT.
I SHALL NOT ATTEMPT
TO VOICE THE QUALITY
OF RESPECT AND ADMIRATION
WHICH CAPTAIN KIRK
COMMANDED.
EACH OF YOU
MUST EVALUATE THE LOSS
IN THE PRIVACY
OF YOUR OWN THOUGHTS.
ATTENTION.
DISMISSED.
THERE IS A DUTY
TO BE PERFORMED
IN THE CAPTAIN'S QUARTERS,
WHICH REQUIRES
OUR PRESENCE.
IT CAN WAIT, DOCTOR.
MY DUTIES REQUIRE
MY IMMEDIATE PRESENCE
ON THE BRIDGE.
THE CAPTAIN
LEFT A MESSAGE TAPE.
IT WAS HIS ORDER THAT IT BE
REVIEWED BY BOTH OF US,
SHOULD HE EVER BE
DECLARED DEAD.
YOU HAVE JUST
DECLARED JIM DEAD.
IT WILL WAIT FOR
A MORE SUITABLE MOMENT,
DOCTOR.
WHY? ARE YOU AFRAID IT'LL
CHANGE YOUR PRESENT STATUS?
THE MENTAL
AND PHYSICAL STATE
OF THIS CREW
ARE YOUR RESPONSIBILITY,
DOCTOR.
AT THE MOMENT,
THEY ARE YOUR
TOP PRIORITY.
THE CAPTAIN'S LAST ORDER
IS TOP PRIORITY,
AND YOU WILL
HONOR THAT ORDER
BEFORE YOU TAKE OVER.
HE WAS A HERO IN EVERY
SENSE OF THE WORD,
YET HIS LIFE
WAS SACRIFICED
FOR NOTHING.
THE ONE THING THAT
WOULD HAVE GIVEN
HIS DEATH MEANING
IS THE SAFETY
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
NOW YOU'VE MADE THAT
IMPOSSIBLE, MR. SPOCK.
WE CAME HERE FOR
A SPECIFIC PURPOSE, DOCTOR.
MAYBE NOT THE SAME ONE.
I REALLY CAME HERE
TO FIND OUT WHY YOU
STAYED AND FOUGHT.
THE CAPTAIN WOULD HAVE REMAINED
TO RECOVER A MEMBER
OF THE CREW
AT THE RISK OF HIS OWN LIFE
OR EVEN THE SHIP.
YES, HE WOULD,
MR. SPOCK,
BUT YOU DIDN'T HAVE
THAT DECISION TO MAKE.
WHAT DID YOU HAVE
TO GAIN BY FIGHTING
THE THOLIANS?
YOU COULD HAVE
ASSURED YOURSELF
OF A CAPTAINCY
BY LEAVING THE AREA.
BUT YOU CHOSE TO STAY.
WHY?
I NEED NOT EXPLAIN
MY RATIONALE TO YOU
OR TO ANY OTHER MEMBER
OF THIS CREW.
THERE IS A MARGIN
OF VARIATION
IN ANY EXPERIMENT.
WHILE THERE WAS A CHANCE,
I WAS BOUND
LEGALLY AND MORALLY
TO ASCERTAIN
THE CAPTAIN'S STATUS.
YOU MEAN TO BE SURE
IF HE WAS DEAD.
WELL, YOU MADE CERTAIN
OF THAT.
THAT IS ENOUGH, DOCTOR.
WE BOTH HAVE
OTHER THINGS TO DO.
YES, I HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO.
IF THIS CREW
IS TO SURVIVE,
I HAVE TO FIND
AN ANTIDOTE
TO THIS SPACE
YOU'VE LOCKED US INTO.
YOU WILL RETURN
TO YOUR DUTY
AS SOON AS WE'VE DISCHARGED
OUR RESPONSIBILITIES HERE.
THERE'S NO HURRY,
MR. SPOCK.
THE ANTIDOTE PROBABLY
DOESN'T CONCERN YOU.
VULCANS
ARE PROBABLY IMMUNE,
SO JUST TAKE YOUR TIME.
I MUST ADMIT I DON'T
UNDERSTAND YOU, SPOCK,
BUT I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT YOU WOULD
WANT JIM'S COMMAND.
BUT YOU MUST KNOW
THAT IF YOU GET US
OUT OF THIS SITUATION,
THEY'LL PIN A MEDAL
ON YOUR CHEST
AND GIVE YOU COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
DOCTOR,
I AM IN COMMAND
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
I WOULD LIKE TO
REMEDY THAT SITUATION.
[BEEP]
IF YOU BELIEVE
I HAVE ACTED IRREGULARLY,
THEN RELIEVE ME OF DUTY.
THAT IS YOUR PREROGATIVE
AS MEDICAL OFFICER
OF THIS SHIP.
BONES, SPOCK...
SINCE YOU ARE
PLAYING THIS TAPE,
WE WILL ASSUME
THAT I AM DEAD.
NOW, THE TACTICAL SITUATION
IS CRITICAL,
AND BOTH OF YOU ARE LOCKED
IN MORTAL COMBAT.
IT MEANS, SPOCK, THAT YOU
HAVE CONTROL OF THE SHIP
AND ARE PROBABLY MAKING
THE MOST
DIFFICULT DECISIONS
OF YOUR CAREER.
I CAN OFFER ONLY
ONE SMALL PIECE OF ADVICE,
FOR WHATEVER
IT'S WORTH--
USE EVERY SCRAP
OF KNOWLEDGE
AND LOGIC YOU HAVE
TO SAVE THE SHIP,
BUT TEMPER YOUR JUDGMENT
WITH INTUITIVE INSIGHT.
I BELIEVE YOU HAVE
THOSE QUALITIES,
BUT IF YOU CAN'T
FIND THEM IN YOURSELF,
SEEK OUT McCOY.
ASK HIS ADVICE.
AND IF YOU FIND IT SOUND,
TAKE IT.
BONES, YOU'VE HEARD
WHAT I'VE JUST TOLD SPOCK.
HELP HIM IF YOU CAN,
BUT REMEMBER,
HE IS THE CAPTAIN.
HIS DECISIONS MUST BE
FOLLOWED WITHOUT QUESTION.
YOU MIGHT FIND THAT HE IS
CAPABLE OF HUMAN INSIGHT
AND HUMAN ERROR.
THEY ARE MOST DIFFICULT
TO DEFEND,
BUT YOU WILL FIND
THAT HE IS DESERVING
OF THE SAME LOYALTY
AND CONFIDENCE
EACH OF YOU
HAVE GIVEN ME.
TAKE CARE.
SPOCK, I...UH...
I'M SORRY.
IT DOES HURT,
DOESN'T IT?
WHAT WOULD YOU
HAVE ME SAY, DOCTOR?
[INTERCOM WHISTLE]
SPOCK HERE.
Scotty:
MR. SPOCK,
WE HAVE A READOUT
ON THE THOLIAN
TRACTOR FIELD.
I THINK WE CAN ESTIMATE
ITS APPROXIMATE
COMPLETION TIME.
I SHALL BE THERE
SHORTLY.
DOCTOR,
I BELIEVE WE EACH HAVE
OUR RESPECTIVE TASKS
TO COMPLETE
BEFORE THE THOLIANS
COMPLETE THEIRS.
AAH!
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN KIRK,
WE THOUGHT YOU WERE...
SPOCK!
MR. SP--
OH, DOCTOR...
I'VE JUST SEEN
THE CAPTAIN.
OF COURSE YOU HAVE, UHURA.
WE WOULD ALL LIKE TO--
HE'S ALIVE.
HE'S ALIVE,
DOCTOR.
OF COURSE.
BELIEVE ME,
I DID SEE HIM.
I DID.
SPOCK!
MR. SPOCK!
YOU'RE GOING TO SICKBAY.
DOCTOR...
DOCTOR,
I'M NOT GOING MAD.
I DID SEE
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I'VE GOT TO GET...
TO MR. SPOCK.
SCOTT TO CAPTAIN.
SPOCK HERE.
PROCEED, MR. SCOTT.
ONE OF OUR CREWMEN
JUST WENT BERSERK,
BUT WE HAVE HIM
UNDER CONTROL
FOR THE MOMENT.
REPORT TO DR. McCOY
ALL SYMPTOMS NOTED
PRIOR TO THE ATTACK.
SPOCK OUT.
[GROANING]
DR. McCOY--
YES, NURSE.
I HAVE THE DIAGNOSIS
OF THE CREWMAN
WHO ATTACKED
ENGINEER SCOTT.
IT WAS DEFINITELY DUE TO
THE DETERIORATING EFFECTS
OF INTERSPACE.
YES, IT'S BEGINNING
TO SPREAD GENERALLY
THROUGHOUT THE SHIP.
ARE WE ANY CLOSER,
DOCTOR?
NO, EXCEPT I'M POSITIVE
THAT IT'S
A THARAGEN DERIVATIVE
THAT'S THE ANSWER.
AND IT BETTER BE
THE NEXT ONE.
AAH!
UHH!
MR. SPOCK DIDN'T
BELIEVE ME EITHER,
DID HE, DOCTOR?
WELL, NOBODY SAW HIM
BUT YOU, UHURA.
THEN I...
DIDN'T REALLY SEE HIM.
DID I?
I DON'T THINK SO.
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
WILL I BECOME
LIKE CHEKOV, DOCTOR?
NO, NO.
WE'RE WORKING HARD.
WE'LL FIND AN ANTIDOTE.
AAH!
WE'RE BEGINNING
TO INTERPHASE.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
SCOTT TO BRIDGE.
BRIDGE. SPOCK HERE.
ARE WE SLIPPING
INTO INTERSPACE?
NEGATIVE. WE ARE RELATIVELY
STABLE AT THE MOMENT.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
I...DON'T BELIEVE IT.
WHAT IS IT, MR. SCOTT?
MR. SCOTT.
MR. SPOCK,
I'VE JUST SEEN
CAPTAIN KIRK.
HE WAS
STANDING THERE JUST
AS PLAIN AS WE ARE,
AND THEN HE
JUST DISAPPEARED.
REPORT TO THE BRIDGE
IMMEDIATELY.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE
UHURA'S STORY.
YOU SUPPOSE THERE'S
ANY TRUTH IN IT?
IN CRITICAL MOMENTS,
MEN SOMETIMES SEE EXACTLY
WHAT THEY WISH TO SEE.
DO YOU SUPPOSE THEY'RE
SEEING JIM BECAUSE THEY'VE
LOST CONFIDENCE IN YOU?
I WAS MERELY STATING
A FACT, DOCTOR.
IT'S GETTING CRITICAL.
THERE HAVE BEEN
A NUMBER OF ASSAULTS
DOWN ON THE LOWER DECKS.
EVEN SCOTTY'S
BEING AFFECTED.
IF SCOTTY GOES UNDER,
THAT'S A FINISH OF
WHATEVER CHANCE WE HAVE
OF GETTING
THE ENTERPRISE
OUT OF HERE.
PLEASE LEAVE THAT
TO ME, DR. McCOY.
I REALIZE THAT THE CREW
ARE YOUR PRIME CONCERN.
YOU CAN BEST SERVE THEM
IN YOUR LABORATORY.
I URGE YOU TO
CONFINE YOURSELF TO IT
UNTIL A REMEDY
HAS BEEN FOUND.
SPOCK!
MUST BE THIS SPACE
IS GETTING TO ME, TOO.
I KNOW IT'S NOTHING
YOU'VE DONE, SPOCK.
I...I'M SORRY.
I UNDERSTAND, DOCTOR.
I'M SURE THE CAPTAIN
WOULD SIMPLY HAVE SAID,
"FORGET IT, BONES."
MR. SPOCK! LOOK!
CAPTAIN?
AM I ALL RIGHT, DOCTOR?
YES, UHURA, YOU'RE FINE.
THEN WHAT I SAW...
IT WAS REAL.
CAPTAIN KIRK'S ALIVE?
WE ALL SAW HIM.
THE CAPTAIN'S
STILL ALIVE.
OHH.
[INTERCOM WHISTLE]
NURSE CHAPEL
TO DR. McCOY.
McCOY HERE.
RESULTS OF
THE LAST THARAGEN TEST
READY FOR YOU, DOCTOR.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
THEN YOUR FEARS
ABOUT THAT PHASER
WERE CORRECT.
IT BLASTED A HOLE
RIGHT THROUGH THAT
CRAZY SPACE FABRIC.
AND ONLY HEAVEN KNOWS
WHERE IT SENT
THE DEFIANT.
EXACTLY.
BUT THE CAPTAIN REMAINED.
ONLY THE OVERLAP TIME
CHANGED.
THE NEXT INTERPHASE
WILL OCCUR...
HERE.
CAN YOU BE READY?
THAT'LL BE
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
AYE, SHE'LL BE
BACK TOGETHER.
BUT WE'LL ONLY HAVE
ABOUT 80% POWER
BUILT UP.
IT WILL HAVE TO DO,
MR. SCOTT.
[BEEP BEEP]
COME.
WHAT HAVE YOU
GOT THERE?
COMPLIMENTS OF THE HOUSE.
TO YOUR GOOD HEALTH
AND THE HEALTH
OF THE CREW.
YOU FOUND THE ANTIDOTE,
DOCTOR.
YES. AND I'VE ORDERED IT
ORALLY OR INTRAVENOUSLY
FOR EVERYONE
ABOARD THE SHIP.
I WOULD LIKE
FOR YOU GENTLEMEN
TO DRINK IT DOWN.
ENSIGN CHEKOV
WAS AFFECTED SO EARLY.
HAS HE RESPONDED TO IT?
HE IS HIS
SMILING SELF AGAIN,
AND I HAVE DISCHARGED HIM
FROM SICKBAY.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S A DILUTED
THARAGEN DERIVATIVE.
THARAGEN--A NERVE GAS
USED BY THE KLINGONS.
AYE!
AND DEADLY, TOO.
WHAT ARE YOU THINKIN'
OF, DOC? YOU'RE TRYING
TO KILL US ALL?
IF I REMEMBER CORRECTLY,
IT CAUSES FATALITY
ONLY WHEN USED
IN PURE FORM.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IN THIS DERIVATIVE
MIXED WITH ALCOHOL,
IT MERELY DEADENS CERTAIN
NERVE INPUTS TO THE BRAIN.
OH, WELL,
ANY DECENT BRAND
OF SCOTCH WILL DO THAT.
OH, WELL,
ONE GOOD SLUG OF THIS,
AND YOU COULD HIT A MAN
WITH PHASER STUN,
AND HE'D NEVER FEEL IT
OR EVEN KNOW IT.
DOES IT MAKE
A GOOD MIX
WITH SCOTCH?
IT SHOULD.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
WELL, DRINK IT DOWN,
SPOCK.
IT'S THE HUMAN THING
TO DO.
THAT'S
A MEDICAL ORDER...
CAPTAIN.
[SIREN]
WELCOME BACK,
LIEUTENANT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YOUR ABSENCE WAS
KEENLY FELT, MR. CHEKOV.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
ESTIMATED TIME
FOR COMPLETION
OF THE THOLIAN WEB.
2 MINUTES, SIR.
ARE THE SHIPS COMPUTERS
PROGRAMMED
FOR ENTRY
INTO INTERSPACE?
YES, SIR. THE SHIP CAN DRIVE
INTO INTERSPACE AT ANY TIME.
SPOCK TO ENGINEERING.
SCOTT HERE.
PREPARE FOR INTERPHASE
IN 15 SECONDS.
AYE, SIR.
STANDING BY.
MR. SPOCK,
THEY'RE GETTING READY
TO CLOSE THE WEB.
INTERPHASE
IN 10 SECONDS,
9,
8,
7,
6,
5...
STAND BY WITH FULL POWER.
4...
SHE'S ONLY UP TO 76%.
IT WILL HAVE TO DO.
1.
READY TO TRANSPORT
ON MY ORDER.
I SEE HIM.
THERE HE IS!
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
SIR,
THE TRACTOR FIELD
IS ACTIVATING.
WE'RE BEING
PULLED OUT OF HERE.
TRY TO MAINTAIN POSITION,
MR. SULU.
I CAN'T, SIR.
ENGINEERING,
BRING SHIP'S POWER
UP TO FULL CAPABILITY.
WHERE ARE WE NOW,
MR. SPOCK?
CAPTAIN, WE HAVE DESTROYED
THE THOLIANS' WEB.
NEGATIVE, ENSIGN.
UTILIZING THE SHIP'S POWER
HAS THROWN US CLEAR OF IT.
COMPUTE THE DISTANCE
FROM THE ORIGINAL LOCATION.
AT ONCE, SIR.
HAVE WE LOST
THE CAPTAIN?
WE SHALL SOON SEE,
LIEUTENANT.
THE SHIP HAS BEEN THROWN
EXACTLY 2.72 PARSECS
DISTANT FROM
OUR PREVIOUS POSITION.
GOOD. SINCE THE CAPTAIN
WAS LOCKED INTO
OUR TRANSPORTER BEAM
WHEN WE WERE THROWN CLEAR
OF THE INTERPHASE AREA,
HE SHOULD'VE BEEN
DRAWN HERE WITH US.
SPOCK TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
McCOY HERE.
THE CAPTAIN'S OXYGEN SUPPLY
IS RUNNING OUT NOW.
ARE YOU STANDING BY
WITH A HYPO OF
TRIOX-COMPOUND FOR HIM?
I'M READY,
MR. SPOCK.
PREPARE TO TRANSPORT ON
THE CAPTAIN'S COORDINATES
ON MY ORDER.
READY,
MR. SPOCK.
MR. SPOCK, IT'S HIM!
IT'S THE CAPTAIN!
I SEE HIM, ENSIGN.
I SEE HIM.
NOW, DOCTOR.
BONES.
WELCOME HOME, JIM.
I HAD A WHOLE UNIVERSE
TO MYSELF
AFTER THE DEFIANT
WAS THROWN OUT.
THERE WAS ABSOLUTELY
NO ONE ELSE IN IT.
I MUST SAY I PREFER
A CROWDED UNIVERSE
MUCH BETTER.
HOW DID YOU TWO
GET ALONG WITHOUT ME?
OH, WE MANAGED.
MR. SPOCK GAVE THE ORDERS,
AND I FOUND THE ANSWERS.
N-NO PROBLEMS
BETWEEN YOU?
NONE WORTH REPORTING,
CAPTAIN.
TRY ME.
MMM, ONLY SUCH
MINOR DISTURBANCES,
AS ARE INEVITABLE
WHEN HUMANS
ARE INVOLVED.
WHICH HUMANS,
MR. SPOCK?
HE MEANS THAT WHEN
HUMANS BECOME INVOLVED
WITH VULCANS, JIM.
AH, YES.
I UNDERSTAND.
WELL,
I HOPE MY LAST ORDERS
WERE HELPFUL
IN SOLVING ANY PROBLEMS
THAT YOU DON'T FEEL
WORTH REPORTING.
ORDERS, CAPTAIN?
WHAT ORDERS ARE YOU
REFERRING TO, JIM?
MY LAST ORDERS.
TH-THE LAST ORDERS THAT
I LEFT FOR BOTH--
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
THE LAST TAPED ORDERS.
OH, THOSE ORDERS.
WELL, THERE WASN'T TIME.
WE NEVER HAD A CHANCE
TO LISTEN TO THEM.
NO. YOU SEE,
THE CRISIS WAS UPON US
AND THEN PASSED
SO QUICKLY, CAPTAIN,
THAT WE...
GOOD.
WELL, I HOPE WE WON'T HAVE
SIMILAR OPPORTUNITIES
TO TEST THOSE ORDERS...
WHICH YOU NEVER HEARD.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 2,
MR. SULU.
WARP FACTOR 2, SIR.