Captain Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STAR DATE 5784.2
WE ARE RESPONDING
TO DESPERATE DISTRESS CALLS
FROM AN UNKNOWN PLANET.
MY SCIENCE OFFICER MR. SPOCK
IS UNABLE TO ACCOUNT FOR THIS,
SINCE HE REPORTED NO SIGNS
OF LIFE ON THE PLANET.
IT IS RICH
IN KIRONIDE DEPOSITS--
A VERY RARE AND LONG-LASTING
SOURCE OF GREAT POWER.
ARE YOU FROM
THE SPACESHIP ENTERPRISE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALEXANDER,
AT YOUR SERVICE.
I SING, I DANCE,
I PLAY ALL VARIETY
OF GAMES,
AND I'M A GOOD LOSER,
A VERY GOOD LOSER.
PLEASE, SIR, TRY TO
BEAR THAT IN MIND.
NOW, WOULD YOU PLEASE
ACCOMPANY ME?
WHO ARE THE INHABITANTS
OF THIS PLANET?
OH, PLATONIANS.
I'M SURE YOU'VE
NEVER HEARD OF US.
OUR NATIVE STAR
IS SAHNDARA.
MILLENNIA AGO,
JUST BEFORE IT WENT NOVA,
WE MANAGED TO ESCAPE.
OUR LEADER LIKED
PLATO'S IDEAS--
PLATO, PLATONIUS. SEE?
IN FACT, OUR PRESENT
PHILOSOPHER-KING, PARMEN,
SOMETIMES CALLS US
PLATO'S CHILDREN,
ALTHOUGH WE SOMETIMES
THINK OF OURSELVES
MORE AS PLATO'S
STEPCHILDREN.
EXCUSE ME. UH, SOMEONE'S
WAITING FOR YOU.
WELCOME
TO OUR REPUBLIC.
WHO AMONG YOU IS
THE PHYSICIAN?
I AM.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
MY SPOUSE. HIS LEG.
COME THIS WAY.
WELL, WHAT HAPPENED
TO THAT LEG?
I SUPPOSE I SCRATCHED IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THIS SHOULD HAVE BEEN
ATTENDED TO IMMEDIATELY.
SHEER IGNORANCE.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU CAN DO?
WELL, WE'RE CERTAINLY
GOING TO TRY.
THE INFECTION
IS MASSIVE.
LET ME GIVE YOU A HYPO
TO EASE THE PAIN.
WHERE?
IN THE ARM.
PHILANA,
THEY CAME TO HELP.
THEY DESERVE BETTER
THAN TO DIE--ARGH!
ALEXANDER,
YOU TALK TOO MUCH.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG.
STAR DATE 5784.3.
DR. McCOY IS ENDEAVORING
TO TREAT THE LEADER
OF A STRANGE
GROUP OF PEOPLE.
WHEN THEIR PLANT NOVAED,
MILLENNIA AGO,
THEY TRANSPORTED THEMSELVES
TO EARTH
DURING THE TIME
OF SOCRATES AND PLATO.
AFTER THE DEATH OF THE GREEK
CIVILIZATION THEY IDOLIZED,
THEY CAME TO THIS PLANET
AND CREATED FOR THEMSELVES
A UTOPIA PATTERNED
AFTER IT.
WHAT IS YOUR PROGNOSIS,
DOCTOR?
I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN I HAVE THE RESULTS.
AND FROM NOW ON,
IT WOULD BE BETTER
IF I HANDLED THE INSTRUMENTS
WITHOUT YOUR HELP.
BONES, I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHY A SIMPLE CUT LIKE THAT
COULD BECOME SO SERIOUS.
NEITHER DO I,
BUT IT HAS.
HOW DO I KNOCK OUT
AN INFECTION
WHEN THE TRICORDER
DOESN'T SHOW
ANY INFORMATION
ON PLATONIUS
BACTERIA?
ALL I CAN DO,
AND THIS IS GONNA
TAKE TIME,
IS TO TRY TO MATCH
HIS BUGS WITH A KNOWN
STRAIN AND HOPE.
YOUR PAN
IS IN JEOPARDY.
MM-HMM.
IT ISN'T NOW.
I WIN.
WELL PLAYED,
ERACLITUS.
I THANK YOU,
DIONYD.
THIS PSYCHOKINETIC
POWER OF YOURS...
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU HAD IT?
2 1/2--
EVER SINCE
OUR ARRIVAL
HERE ON PLATONIUS.
HOW IS THE POWER
TRANSMITTED?
BRAIN WAVES.
DO THESE WAVES CEASE
WHILE YOU ARE ASLEEP?
NO, NOT IF
THEY'RE EMBEDDED
IN THE UNCONSCIOUS.
WHAT ABOUT MEDICINE?
WHY NO DOCTORS?
WE HAVEN'T HAD
ANY PRESSING NEED
FOR THE MEDICAL ARTS.
YOU SEE,
WHILE STILL ON SAHNDARA,
WE INSTITUTED A MASS
EUGENICS PROGRAM.
WE ARE THE RESULT.
PARED DOWN TO
A POPULATION OF 38,
WE'RE PERFECT
FOR OUR UTOPIA.
WE'RE BRED
FOR CONTEMPLATION
AND SELF-RELIANCE...
AND LONGEVITY.
HOW OLD
WOULD YOU SAY I AM?
OH, DON'T BE AFRAID.
I'M NOT VAIN.
35.
THAT OLD?
I STOPPED AGING
AT 30.
WELL, ANYWAY,
YOU'RE OFF
BY 2,000 YEARS.
I'M 2,300 YEARS OLD.
WE WERE MARRIED
VERY YOUNG.
I WAS ONLY 117,
AND HE WAS 128.
SO YOU SEE,
WE SCARCELY HAVE TO
MOVE ANYMORE,
LET ALONE WORK.
THAT'S WHY YOU HAVE
NO RESISTANCE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
A BREAK IN THE SKIN
OR A CUT
CAN BE FATAL.
UH...
UH...UH...
FASCINATING.
I BELIEVE
WE'RE EXPERIENCING
THE PSYCHOKINETIC
MANIFESTATIONS
OF PARMEN'S DELIRIUM.
UHH...
SCOTT TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE IN THE MIDST
OF A STORM.
NO DISCERNIBLE
CAUSE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
THERE'S 10-SCALE
TURBULENCE
RIGHT NOW.
EMERGENCY GYROS
AND STABILIZERS
AT MAXIMUM.
IF THIS
KEEPS UP, CAPTAIN,
WE CAN'T LAST!
ENGINES AT FULL SPEED.
GET HER OUT OF ORBIT
AND INTO SPACE.
I'VE TRIED THAT, SIR.
SHE'S LOCKED TIGHT.
THEN THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO BUT BATTEN
DOWN AND WEATHER.
RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
PARMEN'S MIND IS NOT--
WATCH IT!
HE'S NOT ONLY THROWING
AROUND THE FURNITURE,
HE'S TEARING UP THE
ENTERPRISE AS WELL.
BONES,
KNOCK HIM OUT FAST.
HELP!
SAVE ME!
ALEXANDER--
OH!
STAND BEHIND ME.
OW!
HIS MIND WILL
FIND ME ANYHOW.
OH!
DON'T SAVE HIM.
LET HIM DIE.
THE OTHERS WILL
KILL EACH OTHER
TRYING TO TAKE
HIS PLACE.
HURRY UP WITH THAT SHOT!
NOW, DOCTOR.
UH...
I CAN'T BREATHE.
I'M CHOKING...
BONES!
SHAKE HIM.
BREAK HIS CONCENTRATION.
AHH...
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTT ON
THE ENTERPRISE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
CAPTAIN.
THE TURBULENCE
HAS ABATED.
GOOD. I THINK YOU'LL
FIND THE ORBIT LOCK IS
BROKEN AS WELL.
ASSESS DAMAGE AND REPAIR
WHATEVER IS NECESSARY.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW I CAN EVER
THANK YOU.
NOT ONLY
FOR PLATONIUS,
BUT FOR MYSELF.
NO THANKS IS NECESSARY.
ALEXANDER,
SHOW OUR GUESTS
TO THE SOUTH WING.
OH, THANK YOU. WE MUST
RETURN TO THE SHIP.
I THINK I BETTER
WAIT UNTIL THE
FEVER BREAKS.
WELL...IN THAT CASE,
WE'LL STAY.
ANYTHING YOU WANT,
JUST ASK ME.
ANYTHING.
THANK YOU,
ALEXANDER.
THINK NOTHING OF IT.
YOU SAVED MY LIFE.
LISTEN,
I THINK I SHOULD
TELL YOU THAT--
TELL ME WHAT?
WELL, JUST THAT I
NEVER KNEW ANY PEOPLE
LIKE YOU EXISTED.
WHERE IS EVERYONE?
THEY'RE ALL
IN CHAMBERS...
MEDITATING.
ALEXANDER...
ARE THERE OTHER
PLATONIANS LIKE YOU?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
LIKE ME?
WHO DON'T HAVE
THE PSYCHOKINETIC
ABILITY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
TALKING ABOUT
MY SIZE...
BECAUSE THEY
MAKE FUN OF ME
FOR MY SIZE.
BUT, UM, TO ANSWER
YOUR QUESTION,
I'M THE ONLY ONE
WHO DOESN'T HAVE IT.
I WAS BROUGHT HERE
AS THE COURT
BUFFOON.
THAT'S WHY I'M
EVERYBODY'S SLAVE
AND I HAVE TO BE
10 PLACES AT ONCE
AND I NEVER DO
ANYTHING RIGHT.
HOW DOES ONE
OBTAIN THE POWER?
AS FAR AS I KNOW,
IT JUST COMES TO YOU
SOMETIME AFTER
YOU'RE BORN.
THEY SAY
I'M A THROWBACK,
AND I AM,
AND SO ARE YOU.
SORRY. I SHOULDN'T
HAVE SAID THAT.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
WE'RE HAPPY WITHOUT IT.
YOU KNOW,
I BELIEVE YOU ARE.
LISTEN,
WHERE YOU COME FROM,
ARE THERE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WITHOUT THE POWER
AND MY SIZE?
ALEXANDER,
WHERE I COME FROM,
SIZE, SHAPE, OR COLOR
MAKES NO DIFFERENCE,
AND NOBODY
HAS THE POWER.
NOBODY?
UH, S-SOMEBODY
WANTS ME.
CAPTAIN, IT WILL BE
VERY GRATIFYING
TO LEAVE HERE.
THAT MIGHT NOT BE EASY
SHOULD PARMEN DIE.
EVEN IF HE SHOULDN'T.
YES.
THIS UTOPIA
OF THEIRS
IS ONE OF THE
BEST-KEPT SECRETS
IN THE GALAXY.
SCREENING THEMSELVES
FROM OUR SENSORS,
LOCKING US
INTO ORBIT--
ALL THIS ADDS UP
TO A PATTERN.
JIM,
MY CONCOCTION
ACTUALLY WORKED.
THE FEVER'S
BROKEN.
AND WHAT
RECUPERATIVE
POWERS.
THE INFECTION'S
BEGUN TO DRAIN
ALREADY.
DR. McCOY,
YOU MAY YET CURE
THE COMMON COLD.
IF THERE EVER WAS
A TIME TO GET OUT
OF HERE, IT'S NOW.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
SCOTTY, COME IN.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
PREPARE TO BEAM US UP.
AFRAID I CAN'T
DO THAT, SIR.
EVERYTHING'S FROZEN.
THE TURBULENCE
HIT YOU THAT HARD?
IT'S NOT
THE TURBULENCE, SIR.
DAMAGE TO THE SHIP
IS MINIMAL.
WHAT CAUSED IT?
I DON'T KNOW, SIR,
AND THOSE
ARE THE FACTS.
DID YOU GET UP
INTO SPACE?
NO, SIR. THE ORBIT'S
LOCKED TIGHTER
THAN EVER,
AND SUBSPACE
COMMUNICATION
WITH STARFLEET,
IT'S COMPLETELY
SEVERED.
ALL RIGHT, SCOTTY.
I'LL HANDLE IT
DOWN HERE. STAND BY.
♪ GREAT PAN
SOUNDS HIS HORN ♪
♪ MARKING TIME
TO THE RHYME ♪
♪ WITH HIS HOOF,
WITH HIS HOOF ♪
♪ FORWARD, FORWARD
IN OUR PLAN ♪
♪ WE PROCEED
AS WE BEGAN ♪
BREKEKEKEKX...
KOOOAX...
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
PARMEN WILL DO.
PHILOSOPHER KINGS
HAVE NO NEED
OF TITLES.
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW WHY
THE SHIP'S INSTRUMENTATION
AND WEAPONRY IS FROZEN...
AND WHY THE  ENTERPRISE
IS LOCKED IN ORBIT.
CAPTAIN, PLEASE.
YOU ARE MISTAKEN,
I ASSURE YOU.
PARMEN, I'VE TALKED
TO THE ENGINEER
ABOARD THE SHIP.
WE'VE SHOWED
OUR GOOD FAITH.
NOW YOU SHOW YOURS.
I WANT THE SHIP
RELEASED IMMEDIATELY.
THE AMENITIES, CAPTAIN.
ALLOW ME TO REMIND YOU
THAT I AM THE HEAD OF
THIS PRINCIPALITY.
GUESTS DO NOT COME
BARGING IN HERE,
MAKING DEMANDS
AND ISSUING ORDERS.
GUESTS?
YOU DON'T KNOW
THE MEANING OF THE WORD.
GUESTS AREN'T TREATED
LIKE COMMON PRISONERS.
DO NOT TAKE
THAT TONE WITH ME.
OH!
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
ENTERPRI--
I CAN'T RAISE THEM.
OBVIOUSLY PARMEN
DOES NOT WISH
ANY CONTACT MADE
WITH THE ENTERPRISE.
HE MAY STILL NEED
THE SHIP'S MEDICAL
STORES.
WHY PREVENT CONTACT?
TO SHUT OUT ANY KNOWLEDGE
OF HIS BRUTAL TREATMENT
OF A STARFLEET CAPTAIN.
NO, MR. SPOCK.
ONE THING FOR CERTAIN--
PARMEN ISN'T CONCERNED
WITH MY DIGNITY
OR SAFETY.
AGREED, CAPTAIN.
AND PARMEN WOULDN'T HAVE
TREATED YOU SO BRUTALLY
IF HE HAD ANY INTENTION
OF RELEASING YOU
OR THE ENTERPRISE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T WANT
TO GO, BUT I
CAN'T HELP MYSELF.
[FANFARE]
GENTLE SPACEMEN,
WE ARE ETERNALLY
IN YOUR DEBT.
WE HAVE SOME
TRIFLES FOR YOU.
PLEASE ACCEPT THEM
AS TOKENS
OF OUR GRATITUDE.
THEY STEM FROM THE
VERY SOURCE
OF OUR INSPIRATION.
TO OUR NOBLE
CAPTAIN,
THE SHIELD
CARRIED BY PERICLES,
AS A SYMBOL OF
GALLANT LEADERSHIP.
TO OUR SILENT AND
CEREBRAL MR. SPOCK,
THIS KITHARA
TO PLUCK MUSIC
TO SOOTHE HIS
EVER-ACTIVE BROW.
AND LASTLY,
TO THE PHYSICIAN
DR. McCOY,
WHO SAVED PLATONIUS
AND MY SPOUSE,
THIS ANCIENT
COLLECTION
OF GREEK CURES,
PENNED BY
HIPPOCRATES HIMSELF.
HAS THE ENTERPRISE
BEEN RELEASED YET?
CAPTAIN, WAIT.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING.
MY HUMBLE APOLOGIES.
YOU WERE BADLY USED.
IN MY OWN DEFENSE,
ALLOW ME TO SAY
THAT MY ILLNESS WAS MORE
PROFOUNDLY DISTURBING
THAN I MYSELF REALIZED.
I'M SURE THAT YOU, TOO,
CAPTAIN, HAVE BEEN
OUT OF SORTS
AND HAVE BEEN DRIVEN TO
FITS OF TEMPER AND RAGE.
UNLIKE YOU, HOWEVER,
WHAT I THINK AND FEEL,
WHETHER FOR GOOD OR ILL,
IS INSTANTLY TRANSLATED
INTO REALITY.
SO PLEASE, FIND IT
IN YOUR HEART
TO FORGIVE ME.
CERTAINLY.
HAS THE ENTERPRISE
BEEN RELEASED YET?
IT WILL BE SHORTLY.
THEN GOOD DAY.
AND THANK YOU
FOR THE PRESENTS.
NOT AT ALL.
BUT THERE IS
ONE FINAL REQUEST.
AFTER MY NEARLY
FATAL INFECTION,
IT HAS BECOME
OBVIOUS TO US ALL
THAT WE CANNOT AFFORD
TO BE WITHOUT
A SKILLED PHYSICIAN.
THEREFORE WE SHOULD LIKE
YOU, DR. McCOY,
TO REMAIN.
I'M VERY SORRY,
BUT THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
YOUR DUTIES WILL BE
EXTRAORDINARILY LIGHT.
YOU'LL BE FREE TO READ,
MEDITATE, CONDUCT RESEARCH,
WHATEVER YOU LIKE.
YOU'LL WANT FOR NOTHING.
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WE SHOULD LIKE TO
KEEP IT CORDIAL,
BUT WE ARE DETERMINED
TO HAVE YOU STAY, DOCTOR.
DR. McCOY
SAVED YOUR LIFE.
I AM LOSING
PATIENCE, CAPTAIN.
AND YOU CONSIDER YOURSELF
A DISCIPLE OF PLATO?
WE MANAGE TO LIVE
IN PEACE AND HARMONY.
WHOSE HARMONY,
YOURS?
PLATO WANTED TRUTH
AND BEAUTY
AND ABOVE ALL
JUSTICE.
MY DEAR MR. SPOCK,
I ADMIT THAT CIRCUMSTANCES
HAVE FORCED US
TO MAKE A FEW ADAPTATIONS
OF PLATO,
BUT OURS
IS THE MOST DEMOCRATIC
SOCIETY CONCEIVABLE.
ANYONE CAN,
AT ANY MOMENT,
BE OR DO ANYTHING
HE WISHES,
EVEN TO BECOMING
RULER OF PLATONIUS
IF HIS MIND
IS STRONG ENOUGH.
AND IF HIS MIND
ISN'T STRONG ENOUGH,
HE GETS TORN APART
LIKE ALEXANDER.
OH, COME NOW.
WE AREN'T CHILDREN.
IN YOUR CULTURE,
JUSTICE IS THE WILL
OF THE STRONGER.
IT IS FORCED UPON PEOPLE
BY MEANS OF WEAPONS AND
FLEETS OF SPACESHIPS.
OUR JUSTICE IS THE WILL
OF THE STRONGER MIND,
AND I, FOR ONE,
CONSIDER IT
A VAST IMPROVEMENT.
WE DON'T USE OUR WEAPONS
FOR THE KIND OF
BRUTALITY YOU PRACTICE.
FAREWELL, CAPTAIN.
COME ON, DOCTOR.
McCOY...
I CAN'T MOVE, JIM.
THEY'RE GOING TO
KEEP ME HERE
NO MATTER WHAT.
LEAVE, PLEASE.
NO.
YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
THEY DON'T WANT
TO FORCE YOU.
THEY NEED
YOUR GOOD WILL.
THEY'RE TRYING--
CAPTAIN, GO WHILE
YOU STILL CAN.
WE'RE NOT LEAVING
UNTIL McCOY IS RELEASED.
THIS ISN'T
THE ENTERPRISE.
YOU ARE NOT
IN COMMAND, CAPTAIN.
WHY EVEN
DISCUSS IT?
GET RID OF THEM.
NO, MY DEAR.
THAT MIGHT OFFEND
THE GOOD DOCTOR.
YOU WISH TO STAY?
BY ALL MEANS.
YOU CAN HELP US CELEBRATE
OUR ANNIVERSARY.
IN THE PROCESS,
I HOPE WE CAN PERSUADE YOU
TO JOIN OUR TINY REPUBLIC.
YOU WON'T PERSUADE ME.
I THINK WE WILL.
♪ I'M TWEEDLEDEE,
HE'S TWEEDLEDUM ♪
♪ TWO SPACEMEN
MARCHING TO A DRUM ♪
♪ WE SLITHE AMONG
THE MIMSEY TOVES ♪
♪ AND GYRE AMONG
THE BOROGOVES ♪
YOU'RE NOT STAYING,
McCOY.
NO MATTER
WHAT HE TRIES--
BEING YOUR SLAVE...
WHAT SHOULD I DO
BUT TEND UPON THE HOURS...
AND TIMES...
OF YOUR DESIRE?
I HAVE NO PRECIOUS TIME
AT ALL TO SPEND,
NOR SERVICE TO DO,
TILL YOU--
STOP IT!
DON'T DO THIS
TO HIM, PARMEN!
McCOY...
NO MATTER
WHAT HE MAKES ME...
SAY OR DO...
THE ANSWER'S...NO.
OHH!
NO, PARMEN!
STOP IT!
WELL, DOCTOR?
I HAVE MY ORDERS.
AS YOU WISH,
DOCTOR.
UHH...
IS THIS...
YOUR UTOPIA,
YOUR GRAND VISION
OF THE FUTURE?
YOU DON'T--
AAH!
WE'VE HAD ENOUGH
OR YOUR MORALIZING.
AND WE'VE HAD
TOO MUCH OF YOURS.
YOU WILL NEVER GET ME
TO STAY HERE.
YOU WILL BE HAPPY
TO STAY.
IT TAKES A LITTLE
TIME, DOCTOR,
BUT YOU WILL BE
HAPPY TO STAY.
[LAUGHING]
HE'S A VULCAN.
YOU CAN'T FORCE
EMOTION OUT OF HIM.
YOU MUST BE
JOKING, DOCTOR.
IT'LL DESTROY HIM.
[LAUGHING]
WE CAN'T LET HIM
DIE LAUGHING, CAN WE?
[SOBBING]
I BEG YOU.
SPOCK...
DON'T...
LET THEM...
BREAK YOU.
HOLD ON.
DON'T--
PARMEN...
THEY SAVED
YOUR LIFE.
I'M ASHAMED TO BE
A PLATONIAN.
I'M ASHAMED!
AAH!
[WHINNY]
HOW CAN YOU
LET THIS GO ON?
[WHINNY]
CAN YOU DO
ANYTHING FOR HIM?
THERE'S NO
MEDICINE THAT
CAN HELP HIM.
HE'LL HAVE TO
COME THROUGH
THIS HIMSELF.
I TRUST THEY
DID NOT INJURE YOU
TOO MUCH, CAPTAIN.
MY MUSCLES ARE SORE,
THAT'S ALL.
THE HUMILIATION
MUST HAVE BEEN
MOST DIFFICULT
FOR YOU TO BEAR.
I CAN UNDERSTAND.
THE RELEASE
OF EMOTIONS, MR. SPOCK,
IS WHAT KEEPS US HEALTHY,
EMOTIONALLY HEALTHY,
THAT IS.
THAT MAY BE, DOCTOR,
HOWEVER I HAVE NOTED
THAT THE HEALTHY RELEASE
OF EMOTION
IS FREQUENTLY
VERY UNHEALTHY
FOR THOSE CLOSEST TO YOU.
WHICH JUST
GOES TO PROVE
THAT THERE'S
NO SUCH THING AS
A PERFECT SOLUTION.
SO IT WOULD SEEM.
CAPTAIN.
YES, SPOCK.
DO YOU STILL FEEL
ANGER TOWARD PARMEN?
GREAT ANGER.
AND YOU, DR. McCOY?
YES, SPOCK.
AND HATRED.
THEN YOU MUST
RELEASE IT, GENTLEMEN,
AS I MUST MASTER MINE.
I MIGHT HAVE SERIOUSLY
INJURED YOU, CAPTAIN,
EVEN KILLED YOU.
THEY HAVE EVOKED
SUCH GREAT HATRED IN ME...
I CANNOT ALLOW IT
TO GO FURTHER.
I MUST...
MASTER IT.
CONTROL.
JIM...
THIS IS SENSELESS.
I'VE THOUGHT IT OVER.
I'M STAYING.
YOU CAN'T.
BUT PARMEN HAS PROMISED
ME YOU'LL BE SAFE.
PROMISED?
PARMEN?
HE'D LET US BEAM UP
TO THE ENTERPRISE,
THEN PLUNGE THE SHIP
BACK INTO THE
ATMOSPHERE.
WHY? WHY TRICK ME?
BECAUSE IF HE
KILLED US OUTRIGHT
IN FRONT OF YOU,
YOU'D RETALIATE.
YOU'RE A DOCTOR.
YOU HAVE THE MEANS.
BONES,
I KNOW YOU'RE TRYING
TO DO THE RIGHT THING,
BUT IF ANY ONE
OF US ESCAPED,
PARMEN KNOWS THAT
STARFLEET
WOULD NEVER LET THIS
PLANET GO UNPUNISHED.
SACRIFICE YOURSELF
BY AGREEING TO STAY,
AND YOU SIGN
OUR DEATH WARRANT.
HE'S RIGHT.
I SHOULD HAVE
WARNED YOU.
THEY WERE TREATING YOU
THE SAME WAY THEY TREAT ME,
JUST LIKE ME,
ONLY YOU FIGHT THEM.
ALL THE TIME,
I THOUGHT IT WAS ME,
MY MIND THAT COULDN'T
EVEN MOVE A PEBBLE.
THEY EVEN TOLD ME I WAS LUCKY
THEY BOTHERED TO KEEP ME
AROUND AT ALL,
AND I BELIEVED THEM.
THE ARMS AND LEGS
OF EVERYBODY'S WHIM...
LOOK DOWN.
DON'T MEET THEIR EYES.
SMILE. SMILE...
THOSE GREAT PEOPLE...
THEY WERE GODS TO ME.
BUT YOU SHOWED ME
WHAT THEY REALLY ARE.
NOW I KNOW.
DON'T YOU SEE?
IT'S NOT ME.
IT'S NOT MY SIZE.
IT'S THEM!
PUT IT DOWN.
NO. THIS IS
THE BEST THING
FOR THEM.
PUT IT DOWN.
NO.
DO WHAT I SAY.
I'M GOING TO
CUT THEM.
ALEXANDER.
PARMEN FIRST.
AND THEY'LL ALL
GET INFECTED.
BUT THIS TIME,
WHATEVER THEY SAY,
DON'T SAVE THEM.
LET THEM DIE.
GIVE IT TO ME!
AT LEAST LET ME
GIVE THEM A TASTE
OF WHAT
THEY GAVE ME.
PLEASE. THEY'RE
GONNA KILL YOU
ANYWAY. YOU KNOW THAT.
IN THAT CASE, WHAT'S
THE POINT IN YOU DYING,
TOO, ALEXANDER?
GIVE IT TO ME.
TH-THAT'S
THE FIRST TIME
ANYBODY EVER
THOUGHT OF MY LIFE
BEFORE HIS OWN.
I SHOULD HAVE TOLD YOU
WHEN YOU FIRST CAME HERE
THAT THEY WERE GONNA
KILL YOU,
BECAUSE I KNEW THAT,
BUT I WAS AFRAID.
I WAS AFRAID.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
ALEXANDER.
LISTEN, WE HAVEN'T
GIVEN UP,
AND THERE MAY BE
SOMETHING YOU CAN
DO TO HELP.
ANYTHING I CAN DO
TO HELP,
YOU JUST TELL ME.
ALL RIGHT.
DID THE PLATONIANS
ALWAYS HAVE THIS POWER?
NO, NOT UNTIL WE CAME
TO THIS PLANET.
ALEXANDER, IS IT
POSSIBLE FOR YOU
TO RECALL
HOW LONG AFTER
YOU ARRIVED HERE
THAT THEIR POWER
BEGAN TO DEVELOP?
HOW COULD I FORGET THAT?
IT WAS EXACTLY 6 MONTHS AND
14 DAYS AFTER WE GOT HERE
THAT THEY STARTED
PUSHING ME AROUND.
HOW WOULD YOU
KNOW HOW MANY
MONTHS' SUPPLIES
YOU BROUGHT
WITH YOU?
WELL, FOUR, I THINK.
NO, THREE.
THAT'S CLOSE ENOUGH,
ALEXANDER.
FASCINATING.
THEIR POWER
DEVELOPED TWO
OR THREE MONTHS
AFTER THEY
STARTED EATING
THE NATIVE FOODS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN IT'S LOGICAL
TO ASSUME THAT
THERE'S A CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE
PSYCHOKINETIC POWER
AND THE EATING OF
THE NATIVE FOODS.
THEN WHY WOULDN'T
ALEXANDER HAVE THE SAME
POWER AS THE OTHERS?
PERHAPS HIS SYSTEM
CANNOT ABSORB
THE CRUCIAL ELEMENT.
BONES, I THINK
IT WOULD BE A GOOD IDEA
IF YOU TOOK A READING
OF ALEXANDER'S BLOOD.
UH, NOT THAT I'M
AFRAID OR ANYTHING,
BUT WILL IT HURT MUCH?
YOU WON'T EVEN KNOW
IT HAPPENED.
YOU STILL HAVE A
TRICORDER READING OF
PARMEN'S BLOOD, DON'T YOU?
OF COURSE.
PARMEN POSSESSES
THE HIGHEST ORDER
OF PSYCHOKINETIC
ABILITY,
AND ALEXANDER
THE LOWEST
IN THE SAME
ENVIRONMENTAL
CONDITIONS.
THE PROBABILITIES ARE
THAT ALEXANDER
WAS BORN WITH SOME
BIOCHEMICAL DEFICIENCY
RELATIVE TO PLATONIUS.
I'LL RUN BOTH THEIR
BLOOD SAMPLES THROUGH
FOR A FULL
COMPARATIVE TEST ON
THE TRICORDER.
AND IF OUR THEORY
WORKS OUT,
WE'VE GOT A WEAPON.
THE ONE SIGNIFICANT
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN PARMEN'S
BLOOD AND ALEXANDER'S
IS A CONCENTRATION
OF KIRONIDE
BROKEN DOWN
BY A PITUITARY HORMONE.
KIRONIDE.
IT'S A HIGH-ENERGY SOURCE.
THAT COULD BE IT.
THE PITUITARY HORMONES
CONFIRM THE HYPOTHESIS.
THEY ALSO REGULATE
BODY GROWTH.
OH. YOU MEAN,
THE SAME THING
THAT KEPT ME
FROM HAVING THE POWER
MADE ME A DWARF?
YES.
IT'S ALSO OBVIOUS
WHY PARMEN
KEPT THIS LITTLE
UTOPIA A SECRET.
ANYONE COMING DOWN
HERE AND REMAINING
LONG ENOUGH
WOULD ACQUIRE
THE POWER.
EXACTLY.
McCOY...
THERE MUST BE
A QUICK WAY
OF BUILDING UP
A CONCENTRATION
OF KIRONIDE
IN OUR BLOOD.
IT'LL TAKE SOME DOING,
BUT IT'S POSSIBLE.
WHAT ARE WE
WAITING FOR?
WHAT IS IT,
BONES?
WELL, EVEN IF
THE KIRONIDE REACHES
ITS DESIRED EFFECT,
IT STILL MAY NOT
HELP US GET OUT OF HERE.
YES. THERE ARE
38 OF THEM.
THE POINT IS
WELL TAKEN,
HOWEVER THE PSYCHOKINETIC
POWER IS NOT ADDITIVE.
IF IT WERE,
CONSIDERING THE PLATONIANS'
HOSTILE PROPENSITIES
TWO OR THREE OF THEM
WOULD HAVE COMBINED FORCES
CENTURIES AGO
AND DEPOSED PARMEN.
HE'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, PARMEN SAYS
THAT EACH ONE HAS HIS OWN
SEPARATE POWER FREQUENCY
BECAUSE BEFORE
WHEN THEY'VE TRIED
TO COMBINE THEIR POWERS
AND USE THEM TOGETHER,
IT NEVER WORKED.
I'M READY.
LET'S NOT
WASTE ANY TIME.
GIVE US DOUBLE THE
CONCENTRATION IN
PARMEN'S BLOODSTREAM.
THE TIME FACTOR
CONCERNS ME.
IT MAY TAKE DAYS
OR EVEN WEEKS
BEFORE THERE'S
ENOUGH BUILDUP
FROM THE KIRONIDE
TO BE OF ANY
BENEFIT TO US.
YES...
WHAT ABOUT
ALEXANDER?
SINCE THE KIRONIDE'S
BROKEN DOWN AND INJECTED
DIRECTLY INTO HIS BLOODSTREAM,
IT SHOULD WORK
ON HIM AS WELL AS US--
BETTER, IN FACT, BECAUSE
HE'S ACCLIMATED.
OH, NO.
NOT AFTER WHAT
THEY'VE DONE TO ME.
WHY NOT?
YOU COULD
CONCEIVABLY TAKE
PARMEN'S PLACE
AND RUN
THE WHOLE PLANET.
YOU THINK THAT'S
WHAT I WANT?
BECOME ONE OF THEM,
BECOME MY OWN ENEMY?
JUST LIE AROUND
LIKE A BIG BLOB OF NOTHING
AND HAVE THINGS
DONE FOR ME?
I WANT TO MOVE AROUND
FOR MYSELF.
IF I'M GOING TO
LAUGH OR CRY, I WANT
TO DO IT FOR MYSELF!
YOU CAN KEEP
YOUR PRECIOUS POWER.
ALL I ASK IS ONE THING.
IF YOU DO MAKE IT
OUT OF HERE,
TAKE ME WITH YOU.
JUST DROP ME ANYPLACE
WHERE THEY NEVER HEARD OF
KIRONIDE OR PLATONIUS.
ALEXANDER--
Kirk: NURSE...
LIEUTENANT UHURA?
I GUESS WE WEREN'T
SUFFICIENTLY ENTERTAINING.
ARE WE EVER GLAD
TO SEE YOU.
WE WERE FORCED
IN THE TRANSPORTER
AND BEAMED DOWN.
IT WAS LIKE BECOMING
SOMEONE'S PUPPET.
I THOUGHT I WAS
SLEEPWALKING.
I COULDN'T STOP
MYSELF.
[LAUGHTER]
CAPTAIN,
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[LAUGHTER]
SPOCK, DO YOU FEEL
ANY EFFECT
OF THE KIRONIDE SHOT?
I DID EXPERIENCE
A SLIGHT FLUSH, CAPTAIN.
SO DID I.
LET'S TRY A SIMPLE TEST.
CONCENTRATE ON RAISING
THIS PLATE OF FRUIT.
NOTHING.
[LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE]
FELLOW ACADEMICIANS.
2,500 YEARS AGO,
A BAND OF HEARTY VAGABONDS
ARRIVED ON THIS BARREN,
ROUGH-HEWN PLANET.
THERE WAS
A DESPERATE HARDSHIP
OF BACKBREAKING TOIL.
AND THEN
A DIVINE PROVIDENCE
GRACED OUR GENIUS
AND OUR DEDICATION
WITH THE POWER OF POWERS.
AND THROUGH IT, OUR EVERY
NEED INSTANTLY MATERIALIZED.
WE THEREUPON DETERMINED
TO FORM
A UTOPIAN BROTHERHOOD.
THIS NIGHT IS INDEED
A FESTIVE OCCASION,
FOR TONIGHT, WE WELCOME
INTO THAT BROTHERHOOD
IT'S FIRST NEW MEMBER.
NOT YET, PARMEN.
YOU HAVE TO CONVINCE
THE DOCTOR FIRST.
THEY'LL NEVER DO IT, JIM.
DOCTOR, PLEASE.
YOU ARE DESTROYING
THE FESTIVE MOOD
OF THE LADIES.
WE MUST RECAPTURE IT
AT ONCE.
I KNOW.
WHAT WOULD BE BETTER
THAN A SERENADE FROM
THE LAUGHING SPACEMAN?
[LAUGHING]
♪ ♪
♪
♪ TAKE YOUR YOUNG LADIES
AND VALUE YOUR WINE ♪
♪ BE WATCHFUL OF YOUNG MEN
IN THEIR VELVET PRIME ♪
♪ DEEPLY THEY'LL SWALLOW
FROM YOUR FINEST KEGS ♪
♪ THEN SWIFTLY BE GONE ♪
♪ LEAVING BITTER DREGS ♪
♪ AHH-AH-AH-AH ♪
♪ BITTER DREGS ♪
♪ WITH SMILING WORDS
AND TENDER TOUCH ♪
♪ MAN OFFERS LITTLE
AND ASKS FOR SO MUCH ♪
♪ HE LOVES IN THE BREATHLESS
EXCITEMENT OF NIGHT ♪
♪ THEN LEAVES
WITH YOUR TREASURE ♪
♪ IN COLD MORNING LIGHT ♪
♪ AHH AHH ♪
AND NOW
LET THE REVELS BEGIN.
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
OH, HOW FAITHLESS
AND FICKLE.
MAKE UP YOUR MINDS.
I'M SO ASHAMED.
PLEASE MAKE THEM STOP.
WE HAVE TRIED.
PLEASE!
PLEASE MAKE THEM STOP.
I HAVEN'T THE POWER.
I'M DEEPLY SORRY.
WE FAILED YOU.
FOR SO LONG I'VE WANTED
TO BE CLOSE TO YOU.
NOW ALL I WANT TO DO
IS CRAWL AWAY AND DIE.
CAREFUL, MR. SPOCK.
TOO MUCH LOVE IS DANGEROUS.
REMEMBER--CUPID'S ARROW
KILLS VULCANS.
I'M SO FRIGHTENED, CAPTAIN.
I'M SO VERY FRIGHTENED.
THAT'S THE WAY
THEY WANT YOU TO FEEL.
IT MAKES THEM THINK
THAT THEY'RE ALIVE.
I KNOW IT...
BUT I WISH
I COULD STOP TREMBLING.
TRY NOT
TO THINK OF THEM.
TRY.
I'M THINKING.
I'M THINKING
OF ALL THE TIMES
ON THE ENTERPRISE
WHEN I WAS SCARED TO DEATH...
AND I WOULD SEE YOU
SO BUSY AT YOUR COMMAND
AND I WOULD HEAR YOUR VOICE
FROM ALL PARTS OF THE SHIP...
AND MY FEARS WOULD FADE.
AND NOW THEY ARE
MAKING ME TREMBLE.
BUT I'M NOT AFRAID.
I AM NOT AFRAID.
OH...
[LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE]
PARMEN, LET'S
GET ON WITH IT.
YOU ARE SO IMPATIENT,
MY WIFE.
OBSERVE THE DOCTOR
AND LEARN.
HE'S QUITE CONTENT TO WAIT
FOR THE
PIECE DE RESISTANCE.
YOU'RE HALF DEAD,
ALL OF YOU!
YOU'VE BEEN DEAD
FOR CENTURIES.
WE MAY DISAPPEAR TOMORROW,
BUT AT LEAST
WE'RE LIVING NOW,
AND YOU CAN'T STAND THAT,
CAN YOU?
YOU'RE HALF CRAZY
BECAUSE THERE'S
NOTHING INSIDE. NOTHING.
AND YOU HAVE TO TORTURE US
TO CONVINCE YOURSELVES
YOU'RE SUPERIOR.
STOP IT, PARMEN!
STOP IT!
I'LL DO WHATEVER YOU WANT
ME TO DO.
I'LL STAY HERE AND
SERVE YOU, BUT STOP IT!
PARMEN.
ALEXANDER AGAIN.
HE LIKES TO PLAY
WITH KNIVES.
VERY WELL.
WE SHALL INDULGE HIM.
WHO DID THAT?
I DID.
[ERACLITUS]
IMPOSSIBLE!
QUITE POSSIBLE...
AND LOGICAL.
WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
PLATONIANS,
LISTEN TO ME.
THE NEXT ONE OF YOU
THAT TRIES ANY TRICK
WILL GET HURT.
NOT ONLY DO WE HAVE YOUR
PSYCHOKINETIC ABILITY
BUT AT TWICE
YOUR POWER LEVEL.
NOT TWICE MINE!
CAPTAIN, NO!
CAPTAIN...
I BEG OF YOU!
I'LL DO ANYTHING YOU SAY.
I DO NOT WISH TO DIE.
CAPTAIN...
DO YOU HEAR ME?
DON'T STOP ME.
LET ME FINISH HIM OFF.
DO YOU WANT TO BE LIKE HIM?
PARMEN, LISTEN TO ME.
I COULD HAVE HAD
YOUR POWER,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT IT.
I COULD HAVE HAD
YOUR PLACE RIGHT NOW,
BUT THE SIGHT OF YOU
AND YOUR ACADEMICIANS
SICKENS ME.
DESPITE YOUR BRAINS,
YOU'RE THE MOST
CONTEMPTIBLE THINGS
THAT EVER LIVED
IN THIS UNIVERSE.
CAPTAIN...
YOU KNEW THAT
I INTENDED TO DESTROY
BOTH YOU
AND THE ENTERPRISE,
YET YOU SPARED ME.
TO US,
KILLING IS MURDER,
EVEN FOR REVENGE.
BUT THERE WILL BE
OTHER STARSHIPS.
THERE'S NO NEED
FOR CONCERN.
THEY'LL BE SAFE.
OF LATE,
I HAVE BEGUN TO THINK
THAT WE HAVE BECOME BIZARRE
AND UNPRODUCTIVE.
WE'RE EXISTING MERELY
TO NOURISH OUR OWN POWER.
IT'S TIME
FOR SOME FRESH AIR.
WE SHALL WELCOME
YOUR INTERSTELLAR VISITS.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
THAT WOULD BE HIGHLY
UNCHARACTERISTIC.
WE MUST EXPECT,
PARMEN,
THAT THE MOMENT
WE LEAVE HERE,
YOUR FEAR
WOULD BE GONE
AND YOU'D AGAIN BE
AS SADISTIC
AND AS ARROGANT
AS YOUR 2,500 YEARS
HAVE MADE YOU.
AND JUST REMEMBER,
WE CAN RE-CREATE THAT POWER
IN A MATTER OF HOURS,
SO DON'T TRY ANYTHING.
UNDERSTOOD, CAPTAIN.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT.
NONE OF US CAN BE TRUSTED.
UNCONTROLLED, POWER
WILL TURN EVEN SAINTS
INTO SAVAGES,
AND WE CAN ALL
BE COUNTED UPON
TO LIVE DOWN
TO OUR LOWEST IMPULSES.
YOU'RE VERY GOOD
AT MAKING SPEECHES, PARMEN.
JUST MAKE SURE
THIS ONE SINKS IN.
NOW, MOVE ASIDE.
ALEXANDER.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
MR. SCOTT, PREPARE
TO BEAM US UP.
I HAVE A LITTLE SURPRISE
FOR YOU.
I'M BRINGING
A VISITOR ABOARD.