SHIP'S LOG,
STARDATE 5710.5.
LIEUTENANT COMMANDER
SCOTT REPORTING.
WHILE EXPLORING
AN OUTER QUADRANT
OF THE GALAXY,
THE ENTERPRISE
RECEIVED DISTRESS CALLS
FROM AN APPARENTLY
UNINHABITED,
INCREDIBLY BEAUTIFUL CITY
ON THE PLANET OF SCALOS.
CAPTAIN KIRK
AND A LANDING PARTY
HAVE BEAMED DOWN
TO INVESTIGATE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
WHAT DO YOUR
SENSORS READ?
THEY REGISTER
SOMETHING, SIR,
BUT I'M BLESSED IF I CAN
FIGURE OUT WHAT IT IS.
SPECIFY.
I CAN'T GET
A FIX ON IT.
SENSORS DON'T
PINPOINT A LOCATION.
WE MAY HAVE
A MALFUNCTION.
AND I WANT TO
CHECK CIRCUITS, SIR.
YOU DO THAT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
DOES THE LOCATION
OF THE DISTRESS CALL
CORRESPOND WITH
THIS AREA EXACTLY?
YES, SIR.
I AM STILL
RECEIVING
VISUAL CONTACT.
I CAN SEE THEM,
BUT I CAN'T YOU.
[KIRK]
CHECK COORDINATES.
IS IT THE SAME AREA?
COORDINATES
CORRESPOND, CAPTAIN.
WELL, APART FROM
THE LANDING PARTY,
THERE'S NO ONE HERE.
THERE ARE NO SCALOSIANS.
THE DISTRESS CALL
IS VERY STRONG, CAPTAIN.
THEY ARE PLEADING FOR
IMMEDIATE ASSISTANCE.
CHECK CIRCUITS
FOR MALFUNCTIONS.
KIRK OUT.
IT MUST BE A MALFUNCTION.
THIS IS A BARREN WORLD.
THERE'S HARDLY
ANY VEGETATION,
NO APPARENT ANIMAL LIFE.
WHEN WE RUN
ANALYSIS, WE SHOULD
HAVE SOME
EXPLANATION.
BUT THERE IS
AN INSECT LIFE.
MY TRICORDER
DOESN'T REGISTER IT.
IT REGISTERS
IN MY EARS.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
NOTHING, MR. SPOCK?
EVIDENTLY,
A CIVILIZATION
OF HIGH ORDER,
RATING NUMBER 7 ON
THE INDUSTRIAL SCALE,
HUMANOID IN APPEARANCE,
ACCORDING TO
THE PAINTINGS.
AN ABUNDANCE
OF LITERATURE,
WHICH I SHALL
HAVE TRANSLATED
AND PROCESSED.
CERTAIN STRUCTURES
HOLD EVIDENCE
OF RECENT OCCUPANCY
WHILE OTHERS
ARE APPARENTLY
LONG ABANDONED.
NO SIGN OF PRESENT LIFE.
INSTRUMENT READINGS
INDICATE LIFE FORM,
BUT OF A HIGHLY UNUSUAL
AND INTERMITTENT NATURE.
THEY HAVE NO DISCERNIBLE
FORM OR LOCATION.
A MOST PUZZLING
PHENOMENON, CAPTAIN.
I SHALL HAVE TO
STUDY IT FURTHER.
SOMETHING WAS HERE.
WE SAW THEM
ON THE SCREEN.
LIEUTENANT UHURA
IS STILL GETTING
A DISTRESS CALL.
WHAT HAPPENED?
UNKNOWN AT PRESENT,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK, I WANT
YOU TO RUN A SURVEY--
A COMPLETE SURVEY
OF THE PLANET
USING ALL SHIP'S
AVAILABLE INSTRUMENTS.
COMPTON!
WHAT HAPPENED?
I WAS LOOKING AT HIM.
I WAS LOOKING
RIGHT AT HIM,
AND HE...
AND THEN HE JUST
WASN'T THERE!
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
START A REPLAY
OF THE DISTRESS CALL.
SCOTTY, ARE THE TRANSPORTER
CONTROLS FUNCTIONING NOW?
AYE, SIR.
IS MR. SPOCK
STILL DOWN THERE?
NO, HE'S IN SICK BAY.
DR. McCOY'S
RUNNING A CHECK
ON THE LANDING PARTY.
WHAT IS IT, LIEUTENANT?
MALFUNCTION, SIR.
MR. SULU,
I WOULD LIKE--
CAPTAIN.
IT CORRECTED ITSELF.
CAPTAIN,
THERE'S SOME TROUBLE
ON THE HANGAR DECK.
THE CONTROLS
ARE FROZEN.
HAVE THE REPAIR
CREWS BEEN ASSIGNED?
YES, SIR.
THE TAPE IS READY, SIR.
PLAY IT.
TO ANY AND ALL
SPACE TRAVELERS
PASSING WITHIN RANGE
OF THE PLANET SCALOS,
I SEND YOU AN URGENT
APPEAL FOR HELP.
MY COMRADES AND I
ARE THE LAST
SURVIVING MEMBERS
OF WHAT WAS ONCE
A THRIVING CIVILIZATION.
THOSE OF US
WHO ARE LEFT
HAVE TAKEN SHELTER
IN THIS AREA.
WE HAVE NO EXPLANATION
FOR WHAT HAS BEEN
HAPPENING TO US.
OUR NUMBER IS NOW FIVE.
WE WERE ONCE A NATION
OF 900,000.
FREEZE IT.
IT IS LOGICAL
TO ASSUME
THAT THIS DISTRESS CALL
WAS PRERECORDED.
WHAT WE RECEIVED
WAS EVIDENTLY A
DELAYED TAPED MESSAGE.
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN
OUR CONTINUING
TO RECEIVE IT
WHILE OUR SENSORS PICKED
UP ONLY THE LANDING PARTY, SIR.
NEVERTHELESS, THE
FACT REMAINS THAT
WHEN WE BEAMED DOWN
THERE, WE
COULDN'T FIND
THESE PEOPLE.
THEY WERE THERE,
AND NOW THEY'RE NOT.
NOR IS CREWMAN COMPTON.
IT WOULD SEEM THAT
SOME FORCE OR AGENT
ONLY PARTIALLY
DISCERNIBLE TO
OUR INSTRUMENTS
MAY HAVE BEEN
RESPONSIBLE.
MR. SULU,
I WANT THE SHIP
ON STANDBY ALERT
WHILE WE CONTINUE
THE INVESTIGATION.
SIR, NOW I HAVE
READINGS THAT DEFLECTORS
ARE INOPERATIVE.
THE CONTROLS ARE FROZEN.
SCOTTY, ASSIST.
MR. SPOCK, EVER
SINCE WE BEAMED
UP FROM SCALOS,
WE'VE HAD A SERIES
OF MALFUNCTIONS.
I WANT AN INVESTIGATION
AND AN EXPLANATION.
[INTERCOM SIGNAL]
McCOY TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
CAPTAIN'S PRESENCE
FOR EXAMINATION
IS REQUESTED.
CAN'T IT WAIT,
BONES?
YOUR ORDERS, JIM.
YOU'RE THE LAST ONE.
WHAT DO YOU
READ SO FAR?
CAN WE DISCUSS IT HERE?
ON MY WAY.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
WHAT IS IT?
TELL THE CAPTAIN
WHAT YOU TOLD ME.
SOMETHING'S GOING
ON, CAPTAIN.
SOMEBODY'S OPENED
ALL THE MEDICAL
SUPPLY CABINETS.
ANYTHING MISSING?
JUST DISORDERED,
AS THOUGH SOMEONE
HAD PICKED UP EVERYTHING
AND EXAMINED IT.
THANK YOU.
LIE DOWN, JIM.
WELL, THAT FITS IN
WITH OTHER DISTURBANCES.
BONES, WHAT DID
YOUR READINGS SHOW UP
ON THE OTHER MEN?
ALL PERFECTLY NORMAL.
WHATEVER HAPPENED
TO COMPTON DOWN
THERE
APPARENTLY
HAD NO EFFECT
ON ANYONE ELSE.
ANY OF THEM REPORT
ANY UNUSUAL EXPERIENCE
SINCE BEAMING?
NO. THERE'S NO
MENTION OF IT.
[BUZZING TONE]
I'M NOT FINISHED YET.
HOLD ON.
BONES...
COULD SOMETHING
BE MAKING ME
HALLUCINATE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN THAT TWICE BEFORE
SOMETHING TOUCHED ME.
AND THERE WAS
NOTHING THERE.
AND IT'S JUST
HAPPENED AGAIN.
COULD I BE
IMAGINING IT?
WELL, PHYSICALLY,
THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH YOU.
BUT AM I
HALLUCINATING?
I'D SAY NO.
THEN WE DID BEAM
SOMETHING ABOARD.
[BUZZING]
SOMETHING HAS
INVADED THE SHIP.
[INTERCOM SIGNAL]
KIRK TO SPOCK.
COME IN.
SPOCK, COME IN.
CAPTAIN,
I HAVE A READING
FROM LIFE SUPPORT CENTER...
SPOCK, I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
CHECK YOUR CIRCUITS.
IS THERE A MALFUNCTION?
[UHURA]
CAPTAIN, THE INTERCOM SYSTEM
IS BREAKING DOWN RAPIDLY.
LIEUTENANT,
SHIPWIDE ORDER,
USE COMMUNICATORS
INSTEAD OF INTERCOM.
ISSUE PHASERS
TO ALL CREW MEMBERS.
SPOCK, REPEAT.
I HAVE A READING
FROM LIFE SUPPORT CENTER.
ALIEN SUBSTANCES
BEING INTRODUCED.
MEET ME THERE
ON THE DOUBLE.
SPOCK?
IT IS A FORCE FIELD,
THE NATURE OF WHICH
I AM NOT FAMILIAR WITH.
I'M GETTING READINGS
OF AN ALIEN PRESENCE
SIMILAR TO THOSE OBTAINED
ON THE PLANET'S SURFACE,
BUT THEY SEEM TO HAVE
NO EXACT LOCATION.
PHASERS ON STUN.
SWEEP THE AREA.
IT WOULD SEEM,
CAPTAIN,
THAT THEY INTEND
TO ALLOW
ONLY THE TWO
OF US TO ENTER.
I SHOULD
ADVISE CAUTION.
WHAT IS IT?
UNKNOWN, CAPTAIN.
BUT IT IS
EVIDENTLY A DEVICE
OF ALIEN ORIGIN.
HOOKED INTO
THE LIFE SUPPORT.
DESIGNED TO AFFECT IT?
LIFE SUPPORT IS
STILL OPERATING.
I WOULD SAY THAT
THE INSTALLATION
IS INCOMPLETE.
DISCONNECT IT.
[STATIC]
DESTROY IT.
THAT WAS NO FORCE FIELD.
SOMETHING SHOVED ME BACK.
THEY'RE IN HERE.
YOU!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MY SHIP?
SHOW YOURSELVES!
[BUZZING]
[ZZZZ]
IT SEEMS THAT
WE MAY LOOK
AT IT, CAPTAIN,
BUT THAT IS ALL.
A SHOW OF STRENGTH.
YES. EVIDENTLY,
THEY'RE CONVINCED
THAT WE CAN DO
NOTHING TO STOP THEM,
AND THEY WISH
TO IMPRESS UPON US
WHAT THEY CAN DO TO US.
HAVE YOUR READINGS
BEEN FED INTO THE COMPUTER?
AFFIRMATIVE.
READ OUT.
COMPUTER,
ANALYZE AND REPLY.
HAVE WE BEEN INVADED?
AFFIRMATIVE.
NATURE AND DESCRIPTION
OF ENEMY FORCES.
DATA INSUFFICIENT.
NUMBER OF ENEMY FORCES.
PURPOSE
OF THE INVASION?
IMMEDIATE PURPOSE--
SEIZURE AND CONTROL
OF FEDERATION STARSHIP
ENTERPRISE AND CREW.
DATA INSUFFICIENT
FOR DETERMINATION
OF END PURPOSE.
IS THERE A CONNECTION
BETWEEN THIS
AND COMPTON'S
DISAPPEARANCE?
DATA INSUFFICIENT.
ARE WE AT PRESENT
CAPABLE OF RESISTING?
NEGATIVE.
YOUR RECOMMENDATION?
IF INCAPABLE
OF RESISTANCE,
NEGOTIATE FOR TERMS.
WE WILL NOT
NEGOTIATE.
DO YOU CONCUR?
AYE.
MR. SPOCK?
YOUR RECOMMENDATIONS,
CAPTAIN?
YEOMAN, IS THAT
COFFEE AVAILABLE,
OR HAVE THOSE CIRCUITS
BEEN DAMAGED AS, WELL?
MY RECOMMENDATION?
MAKE THEM
TAKE THE NEXT STEP.
[BUZZING]
SPOCK?
CAPTAIN.
WOULD YOU MIND
EXPLAINING--
WHO ARE YOU?
DEELA.
THE ENEMY.
YOU'RE THE ENEMY?
YES.
YOU BEAMED ME ABOARD
YOURSELF WHEN
YOU CAME UP.
A RIDICULOUSLY
LONG PROCESS,
BUT I'VE TAKEN
CARE OF IT.
WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE WITH MY MEN?
NOTHING.
NOTHING?
MR. SPOCK?
SCOTTY.
THIS IS NOTHING?
THERE'S REALLY
NOTHING WRONG WITH THEM.
THEY ARE JUST AS
THEY HAVE ALWAYS BEEN.
IT'S YOU WHO
ARE DIFFERENT.
LIEUTENANT.
SULU.
THIS IS NOTHING?
WELL, THEY CANNOT
HEAR YOU, CAPTAIN.
TO THEIR EARS, YOU
SOUND LIKE AN INSECT.
OH, THAT'S YOUR
DESCRIPTION, CAPTAIN.
ACCURATE, IF UNFLATTERING.
REALLY, THERE IS NOTHING
WRONG WITH THEM.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
CHANGED YOU.
SO YOU ARE LIKE ME NOW.
YOUR CREW CANNOT
SEE YOU OR ANY OF US
BECAUSE OF THE ACCELERATION.
WE MOVE IN THE
WINK OF AN EYE.
WELL, THERE IS NO SCIENTIFIC
EXPLANATION FOR IT,
BUT ALL THAT REALLY
MATTERS IS THAT...
YOU CAN SEE ME
AND TALK TO ME...
AND...
WE CAN GO ON FROM THERE.
WHY?
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU.
DIDN'T YOU GUESS?
OR ARE YOU SO ACCUSTOMED
TO BEING KISSED
BY INVISIBLE WOMEN?
UH...
UM...
DEELA.
IS THIS WHY
YOU SABOTAGED MY SHIP?
OH, BUT IT HAS NOT
BEEN SABOTAGED.
WE...WE HAD TO MAKE
SOME CHANGES IN IT
TO ADJUST IT TO US.
YOU SAID WE?
YES, OF COURSE.
MY CHIEF SCIENTIST
AND HIS CREW.
I AM THEIR QUEEN.
YOU ARE GOING TO
BE THEIR KING.
YOU'LL ENJOY
LIVING ON SCALOS.
WHAT ABOUT MY SHIP?
MY CREW?
OH, IN A FEW
OF THEIR MOMENTS,
THEY WILL REALIZE
THAT YOU VANISHED.
THEY WILL LOOK FOR YOU,
BUT THEY WILL
NOT FIND YOU.
YOU'RE ACCELERATED FAR
BEYOND THEIR POWER TO SEE.
SO THEY'LL GO ON
WITHOUT YOU.
DON'T BE SO STUBBORN.
YOU CANNOT GO BACK
TO THEM, EVER.
IS IT SO DREADFUL
A PROSPECT?
THIS WON'T KILL YOU,
BUT THE STUN EFFECT
IS NOT VERY PLEASANT.
BUT--BUT THAT WON'T WORK.
WELL, YOU GO AHEAD. TRY.
POINT RIGHT AT ME.
MY REACTIONS
ARE MUCH TOO FAST
FOR SUCH A CRUDE WEAPON.
AND I AM QUITE GOOD
AT SELF-DEFENSE, TOO.
THIS CAN BE SET FOR STUN
AND DESTROY, TOO,
LIKE YOURS.
PLEASE...
ACCEPT WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
THERE IS NOTHING
YOU CAN DO TO CHANGE IT.
IF I AGREE
TO GO WITH YOU,
WILL YOU SET THIS
SHIP TO RIGHTS?
TAKE OUT THAT DEVICE IN
THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEM?
DON'T BE SO SILLY.
YOU'LL FEEL BETTER ABOUT
IT ALL IN A LITTLE WHILE.
IT ALWAYS HAPPENS
THIS WAY.
THEY ARE VERY
UPSET AT FIRST,
THEN IT WEARS OFF,
AND THEY...
THEY LEARN TO LIKE IT.
YOU WILL, TOO.
HE'S ON HIS WAY TO YOU.
BE GENTLE WITH HIM.
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK!
HE'S GONE!
LIEUTENANT, DID YOU
SEE WHAT HAPPENED?
WELL, HE WAS SITTING THERE.
HE'D JUST DRUNK HIS COFFEE
AND SET THE CUP DOWN.
SEE, IT'S STILL THERE.
AND THEN HE VANISHED.
MR. SULU,
DO YOU VERIFY?
THAT'S JUST THE
WAY IT HAPPENED.
HE WAS THERE, THEN
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
HE WASN'T THERE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
YOU'VE MADE IT.
COMPTON, DID THEY
ACCELERATE YOU?
YES, SIR.
THEY'VE HOOKED SOMETHING
INTO THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEM.
THEY'RE IN THERE.
WE'VE GOT TO GET RID OF IT.
LET'S GO.
I'M SORRY, SIR,
ENTRY IS FORBIDDEN.
BY WHOSE ORDER?
THE COMMANDER SIR.
YOU'LL HAVE TO
STEP BACK, PLEASE.
I'M YOUR COMMANDER, COMPTON.
AND I ORDER YOU
TO LET ME IN.
OH, I'M SORRY,
SIR, YOU ARE
NO LONGER.
WHO IS, DEELA?
IS THAT WHO
YOU'RE WORKING FOR?
AT FIRST
I REFUSED.
BUT THEN AFTER A
WHILE, I FOUND THAT
I COULDN'T
HELP MYSELF.
I MET THIS GIRL.
SHE'S ONE OF THEM.
I'VE NEVER KNOWN
ANYONE LIKE HER.
SHE BROUGHT ME ABOARD
AND I SHOWED THEM THE
OPERATION OF THE SHIP.
BRIDGE CONTROLS,
LIFE SUPPORT.
SHE EXPLAINED THAT
THEY WANTED TO KNOW.
I DIDN'T UNDERSTAND
AT FIRST.
BUT I DO NOW.
SO WILL YOU, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, COMPTON.
STUN.
YOU WERE ORDERED
TO STOP HIM.
WHY DID YOU DISOBEY?
I TRIED TO STOP HIM.
YOU HURT HIM.
HE WAS VIOLENT.
HE HAD TO BE SUBDUED.
HE WAS MY CAPTAIN.
CELL DAMAGE.
ANOTHER WILL BE
SECURED FOR YOU.
I'M GETTING A TRACE READING
SIMILAR TO THAT
ON THE PLANET.
MR. SULU, DID YOU
DRINK YOUR COFFEE?
YES.
DID ANYONE ELSE?
I HAD SOME.
MAY I?
WAS IT THE COFFEE?
ARE WE GOING TO GO,
TOO, JUST LIKE
THE CAPTAIN?
I CANNOT GIVE
YOU THAT ANSWER
UNTIL THESE
HAVE BEEN ANALYZED.
WELL, BY THAT
TIME, IT'LL BE
TOO LATE--
I SUGGEST THAT WE RECALL
THE CAPTAIN'S WORDS,
"MAKE THEM TAKE
THE NEXT STEP."
IT WOULD SEEM
THEY HAVE TAKEN IT.
AND WE MUST DETERMINE
EFFECTIVE COUNTERMEASURES.
MR. SCOTT,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
I SHALL BE IN
THE MEDICAL LAB.
I HATE WHAT
HAPPENS TO THEM
WHEN THEY'RE DAMAGED.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO LEARN TO CONTROL
YOUR TEMPER, RAEL.
I DO NOT WANT THAT
TO HAPPEN TO THIS ONE.
IF THEY ARE SO
STUBBORN A SPECIES,
PERHAPS THEY
WILL LAST LONGER.
IT MAY BE.
I HOPE SO.
THEY ALL GO SO SOON.
I WANT TO KEEP THIS
ONE A LONG TIME.
HE'S PRETTY.
HE IS INFERIOR, DEELA.
OH?
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU CANNOT ALLOW
YOURSELF TO FEEL
AN ATTACHMENT TO SUCH.
I CAN ALLOW MYSELF
ANYTHING I WANT.
OH, RAEL, DON'T
BE LIKE THAT.
AM I JEALOUS
OF WHAT YOU DO?
I DO MY DUTY.
SO DO I.
AND SOMETIMES
I ALLOW MYSELF
TO ENJOY IT.
HELLO.
WHAT IS THAT DEVICE
DOING ON MY SHIP?
DEELA WILL EXPLAIN IT.
I WILL TELL YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW.
AND YOU'LL APPROVE OF IT.
APPROVE OF IT?
WE'RE YOUR PRISONERS.
HARDLY. YOU'RE FREE
TO GO ANYWHERE
YOU WANT TO.
GO AHEAD, CAPTAIN.
IT IS NOT YET
COMPLETELY LINKED TO
YOUR SUPPORT SYSTEM,
BUT IT IS IN
OPERATING ORDER.
STUDY IT
IF YOU WISH.
I SUGGEST THAT
YOU DO NOT TOUCH IT.
[ELECTRICITY]
HE TOLD YOU NOT TO TOUCH IT.
LOOK AT YOUR HANDS.
THEY'RE ALMOST FROZEN,
AREN'T THEY?
IT WILL PASS.
THE UNIT HAS ITS OWN
SELF-DEFENSE MECHANISM,
AS YOU SEE.
YOU SHOULD'VE HEEDED ME.
IN YOUR STRUGGLE
WITH COMPTON,
SOME OF HIS CELLS
WERE DAMAGED.
THOSE NEWLY
ACCELERATED
TO OUR LEVEL
ARE SENSITIVE
TO CELL DAMAGE.
THEY AGE VERY
RAPIDLY AND DIE.
HE WAS SO YOUNG.
WAS.
IS THIS WHAT YOU
HAVE PLANNED FOR US?
WE ALL DIE...
EVEN ON SCALOS.
WHY DID YOU
LIE TO HIM?
HE DID NOT
DAMAGE THAT ONE,
YOU DID.
PERHAPS HE WILL
BE LESS VIOLENT NOW.
I SEE NO REASON
TO MAKE HIM
FEEL ANY WORSE
THAN HE HAS TO.
WHY DO YOU CARE
WHAT HE FEELS?
RAEL, HE'S NOT
ONE OF US.
HE'S TEMPORARY.
WHY, HE'S GONE TO
THE MEDICAL LABORATORY.
HE'S TRYING TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THE VULCAN.
HIS SPECIES IS CAPABLE
OF MUCH AFFECTION.
I HAVE NOTED THAT.
I WONDER IF THEY WILL
DEMONSTRATE IT TO US.
OH, RAEL,
STOP SULKING.
ACCEPT IT.
WE'VE HAD TO ACCEPT
IT ALL OUR LIVES.
DON'T MAKE IT WORSE.
GO BACK TO WORK.
KIRK TO SPOCK,
I HAVE FED ALL
THE ASCERTAINABLE FACTS
INTO THE COMPUTER BANKS.
GO AHEAD.
YOU WON'T
ACCOMPLISH ANYTHING,
BUT IT MAY BE
HISTORICALLY VALUABLE.
HYPER-ACCELERATION
IS THE KEY.
I HAVE COUNTED
ONLY FIVE OF
THEM ABOARD,
BUT THEY HAVE
TAKEN OVER THE SHIP,
AND WE ARE UNDER
THEIR CONTROL DUE
TO THIS ACCELERATION.
THEY ARE ABLE
TO SPEED OTHERS
UP TO THEIR LEVEL,
AS THEY DID
COMPTON AND ME.
PRESUMABLY, THIS IS...
ENSLAVEMENT?
THOSE SO TREATED
EXIST AT THIS
ACCELERATED LEVEL,
BECOMING DOCILE
EVENTUALLY.
BUT WHEN...
DAMAGED.
DAMAGED...
THEY AGE
INCREDIBLY FAST,
AS THOUGH
ACCELERATED LIVING...
BURNS THEM OUT.
COMPTON WAS BURNED OUT.
THE DEVICE ATTACHED TO
THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEMS
PRODUCES AN EXTREME
NUMBING COLD.
IT IS MY BELIEF
THAT THEY ARE TURNING
THE ENTERPRISE
INTO A GIGANTIC
DEEP-FREEZE...
FOR PURPOSES ONLY
THE SCALOSIANS KNOW.
QUITE CORRECT.
THE UNIT HAS A
PROTECTIVE SHIELD
WHICH DOES NOT ALLOW
ANY PHYSICAL CONTACT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO DESTROY IT,
BUT ITS DESTRUCTION
IS IMPERATIVE.
THE UNIT WILL BE ACTIVATED.
BY THE TIME THEY HEAR THIS,
IT WILL BE TOO LATE.
YOU HAVE REMARKABLE
REASONING POWERS, CAPTAIN.
YOU WERE QUITE RIGHT
IN ALMOST EVERY ASSUMPTION.
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
DO YOU REALLY
WANT TO KNOW?
IN A LITTLE WHILE, IT
WON'T MATTER TO YOU AT ALL.
YOU'LL BE QUITE
HAPPY ABOUT IT,
JUST AS COMPTON WAS.
I REALLY
WANT TO KNOW.
OH, DEAR.
YOU ARE SO STUBBORN.
IT SHOULD BE OBVIOUS TO
YOU THAT WE'RE DOING IT
BECAUSE WE HAVE TO.
A LONG TIME AGO--
IT IS IN OUR HISTORY--
WE USED TO BE LIKE YOU.
THEN OUR COUNTRY
WAS ALMOST DESTROYED
BY VOLCANIC ERUPTIONS.
THE WATER WAS POLLUTED.
RADIATION WAS RELEASED.
THAT CHANGED US.
IT ACCELERATED US.
THE CHILDREN DIED.
MOST OF THE WOMEN FOUND
THEY COULD NOT HAVE ANY MORE.
ALL OF OUR MEN
HAD BECOME STERILE.
SO WE HAD TO MATE
OUTSIDE OUR OWN PEOPLE.
WHENEVER A
SPACESHIP CAME BY,
WE'D SEND OUT CALLS FOR HELP.
BUT ACCELERATING
THEM TO OUR LEVEL
BURNED THEM OUT.
DON'T YOU SEE, CAPTAIN?
DO I HAVE TO GO
INTO EVERY DETAIL?
WE ARE GOING TO TAKE
YOU DOWN WITH US.
PERHAPS ONE OR TWO
OTHERS OF YOUR CREW.
WE HAVE TO.
OH, WE'LL BE KIND TO YOU.
I WOULDN'T HURT
YOU, CERTAINLY.
I DO LIKE YOU.
WHAT ABOUT THE
REST OF MY CREW?
THEY WILL REMAIN HERE
IN SUSPENDED ANIMATION.
OH, IT WILL DO
THEM NO HARM.
WE ARE SAVING THEM
FOR WHEN WE NEED
THEM IN THE FUTURE.
WELL, YOU WILL
NOT LAST FOREVER.
YOU KNOW THAT, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, WE HAVE
THE RIGHT TO SURVIVE.
NOT BY KILLING OTHERS.
WELL, YOU WOULD DO
EXACTLY THE SAME THING.
YOU CAME CHARGING DOWN
INTO THAT LIFE SUPPORT ROOM
THE MINUTE YOU KNEW
THERE WAS TROUBLE.
YOU WOULD'VE KILLED EVERY
ONE OF MY PEOPLE IF YOU
COULD'VE.
YOU INVADED MY SHIP.
YOU THREATENED MY CREW.
THERE IS NO DIFFERENCE.
THERE IS A DIFFERENCE!
YOUR TROUBLE IS IN YOU.
WE DID NOT ASK FOR IT.
WE ARE NOT TO BLAME.
WE ARE HANDLING IT IN
THE ONLY WAY WE KNOW HOW--
THE WAY OUR PARENTS DID, AND
THEIR PARENTS BEFORE THEM.
DID THEY
SOLVE ANYTHING?
HAVE YOU TRIED
ANY OTHER WAY?
DEELA, HAVE YOUR
SCIENTISTS DISCONNECT,
DESTROY THAT UNIT.
I PROMISE YOU,
WE'LL USE EVERY SKILL
WE HAVE TO HELP YOU.
WE'LL MOVE YOU
TO ANOTHER PLANET
IT THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
WE'LL CALL ON THE MOST
BRILLIANT MINDS
IN OUR FEDERATION
TO HELP.
WE'LL DO--
WE HAVE TRIED
OTHER WAYS.
WE'VE TRIED TO MAKE
THE TRANSITION
TO YOUR LEVEL.
SOME OF US, THAT IS.
THOSE WHO MADE
THE ATTEMPT DIED.
WE ARE TRAPPED,
CAPTAIN,
JUST AS YOU
ARE TRAPPED NOW.
I'M SORRY FOR WHAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN TO YOU,
BUT I CANNOT CHANGE IT.
YOU CANNOT CHANGE ME.
[BEEPING]
GO TO THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM, DEELA.
SIGNAL ME
WHEN YOU'RE THERE
AND BEAM DOWN.
WITH THE CAPTAIN?
YES.
I'LL ACTIVATE OUR UNIT
AND FOLLOW YOU.
I'M SETTING IT
TO ALLOW ENOUGH
TIME FOR ALL OF US
TO GET OFF THE SHIP.
PLEASE DON'T DELAY.
JUST WHAT MAKES YOU
THINK I WOULD DO
THAT?
THE CAPTAIN'S GONE.
WELL, GO AFTER HIM, DEELA.
THERE'S NO QUESTION
ABOUT IT, SPOCK.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
THE SAME SUBSTANCE
IS IN THE CAPTAIN'S
COFFEE
AS IN THE
SCALOSIAN WATER,
AND THERE'S NO TRACE OF
IT ANY OF THE OTHER CUPS.
HMM.
WHY DID YOU RUN?
I PANICKED.
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
I'D LIKE TO LEAVE
BEFORE HE ACTIVATES
THE SUSPENDED
ANIMATION DEVICE.
WE'RE IN THE
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
YOU CAN ACTIVATE.
BEAM HIM DOWN AT ONCE.
CAPTAIN?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE TO
THE TRANSPORTER, CAPTAIN?
IT WAS WORKING BEFORE.
TRY IT AGAIN.
THE TRANSPORTER
ISN'T WORKING.
WHAT'D HE DO TO IT?
NOTHING, HE
DIDN'T HAVE TIME.
IT MUST BE A--
WHAT DO YOU CALL IT--
A MALFUNCTION.
YOU'D BETTER NOT
ACTIVATE THE UNIT YET.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
IT IS, CAPTAIN?
THE TECHNICIANS REPORTED
A LOSS OF POWER.
THAT MUST BE IT.
THE CAPTAIN SAYS
HIS TECHNICIANS--
I HEARD HIM.
YOU EXPECT ME
TO BELIEVE HIM?
I EXPECT YOU TO CHECK
INTO ALL POSSIBLE CAUSES.
IF I HAD A SUSPICIOUS
NATURE, CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SAY
THAT YOU SABOTAGED
THE TRANSPORTER
TO BUY TIME.
YES, OF COURSE.
I'M GLAD
WE'RE BOTH INNOCENT.
I DESPISE DEVIOUS
PEOPLE, DON'T YOU?
OH, I BELIEVE IN HONEST
RELATIONSHIPS MYSELF.
NURSE, PROGRAM
THE INFORMATION
AND DETERMINE
WHETHER WE CAN
FIND COUNTERAGENTS.
[BUZZING]
DOCTOR,
DID YOU JUST--
I'VE BEEN HEARING
THAT WHINE
EVER SINCE WE BEAMED
DOWN TO SCALOS.
MM-HMM.
I KNOW WHAT IT IS.
WE BROUGHT IT
WITH US FROM SCALOS.
IF YOU'LL EXCUSE
ME, DOCTOR,
I SHALL BE
ON THE BRIDGE.
YOUR QUARTERS ARE QUITE
LIKE YOU, CAPTAIN--
AUSTERE AND EFFICIENT...
AND IN THEIR OWN
WAY, HANDSOME.
A ROOM SHOULD
REFLECT ITS OCCUPANT.
ABSOLUTELY.
MAY I FRESHEN UP?
ALL THIS RUSHING ABOUT
HAS LEFT ME WINDBLOWN.
I'M GLAD TO SEE THAT
YOU ALLOW YOURSELF
SOME COMFORTS.
ARE YOU MARRIED, CAPTAIN?
NO FAMILY?
NO ATTACHMENTS?
I KNOW--YOU'RE
MARRIED TO YOUR CAREER,
AND YOU NEVER LOOK
AT ANOTHER WOMAN.
WELL, IF SHE'S
PRETTY ENOUGH,
I'LL LOOK.
I WONDERED WHEN YOU'D
SAY SOMETHING NICE TO ME.
AM I MORE
PRESENTABLE NOW?
A BIT.
IT WAS QUITE DELIGHTFUL
KISSING YOU
WHEN YOU COULDN'T SEE ME.
BUT NOW...
OH.
NO.
I WOULDN'T ALLOW
YOU TO TAKE THAT,
NO MATTER HOW MUCH
WE TRUST EACH OTHER.
BUT I WOULD'VE BEEN
DISAPPOINTED
IF YOU HADN'T TRIED.
WAS I...TOO CRUDE?
JUST DON'T TRY IT AGAIN.
YOU'RE FAR TOO
VULNERABLE TO
SKIN DAMAGE.
ALL I HAVE TO DO
IS SCRATCH YOU.
YES, I KNOW.
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN US
IS THAT YOU WILL
COME AROUND
TO OUR WAY OF THINKING
SOONER OR LATER.
BUT IT'S BETTER
SOONER THAN LATER.
LIEUTENANT,
WILL YOU REPLAY
THE SCALOSIAN
DISTRESS CALL
ON MY VIEWER?
AYE, SIR.
TO ANY AND ALL
SPACE TRAVELERS
PASSING WITHIN RANGE
OF THE PLANET SCALOS,
I SEND YOU AN URGENT
APPEAL FOR HELP.
MY COMRADES AND I
ARE THE LAST
SURVIVING MEMBERS
OF WHAT WAS ONCE
A THRIVING CIVILIZATION.
COMPTON!
WHAT HAPPENED?
I WAS LOOKING AT HIM.
I WAS LOOKING
RIGHT AT HIM,
AND THEN HE JUST
WASN'T THERE!
THOSE OF US
WHO ARE LEFT
HAVE TAKEN SHELTER
IN THIS AREA.
[SLOWING DOWN]
WE HAVE NO EXPLANATION FOR
WHAT HAS BEEN HAPPENING TO
US.
[REWINDING]
[SPEEDING UP]
THOSE OF US
WHO ARE LEFT
HAVE TAKEN SHELTER
IN THIS AREA.
WE HAVE NO EXPLANATION FOR
WHAT HAS BEEN HAPPENING TO
US.
OUR NUMBER IS NOW 5.
WE WERE ONCE A
NATION OF 900,000...
THE CITY ALONE HOLDING
A TOTAL POPULATION OF
113,477 CITIZENS.
OUR PLANET, SCALOS, ON
WHICH EXISTED SEVERAL
CULTURALLY ENLIGHTENED
INDIGENOUS POPULATIONS...
[FAST FORWARDING]
[SPEEDS TO BUZZING]
THERE IS
INSECT LIFE.
MY TRICORDER
DOESN'T REGISTER IT.
MY EARS REGISTER IT.
THIS IS A BARREN WORLD--
LIMITED VEGETATION,
NO APPARENT ANIMAL LIFE.
[HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
[BUZZING]
McCOY TO SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
I FOUND A TAPE
IN THE COMPUTER
DOWN HERE.
AND WHEN I TRY
TO READ IT, ALL
I GET IS A WHINE.
BRING IT TO THE BRIDGE
AT ONCE, DOCTOR.
THIS DEVICE ATTACHED TO
THE LIFE SUPPORT SYSTEM
PRODUCES AN EXTREME
NUMBING COLD.
IT IS MY BELIEF
THAT THEY ARE
TURNING THE ENTERPRISE
INTO A GIGANTIC
DEEP-FREEZE.
THE UNIT HAS
A PROTECTIVE SHIELD
WHICH DOES NOT ALLOW
ANY PHYSICAL CONTACT.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DESTROY IT,
BUT ITS DESTRUCTION
IS IMPERATIVE.
[DEELA]
THE UNIT WILL BE ACTIVATED.
BY THE TIME
THEY HEAR THIS,
IT WILL BE TOO LATE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
NOTIFY THE REST
OF THE CREW.
AYE, SIR.
CAN WE USE PHASERS
TO CUT THROUGH THAT
WALL, BYPASS THE
FORCE FIELD AND
GET AT THAT UNIT?
MR. SCOTT, WE
CANNOT COPE WITH
THEM ON OUR LEVEL.
CAN WE FIND SOME
WAY OF COPING WITH
THEM ON THEIRS?
THAT IS A VERY
LOGICAL SUGGESTION.
PLEASE STAND BY IN
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
ELSEWHERE, SIR.
SUFFICIENT ENERGY
FOR BEAMING DOWN.
THIS IS THE ONLY DAMAGE?
WELL, GO GET THE OTHERS
AND BRING THEM UP HERE.
[NECKBAND BEEPS]
DEELA?
DEELA!
RAEL!
RAEL, STOP.
NO.
NOW STOP IT.
DID HE DAMAGE
YOU, CAPTAIN?
NO.
HOW VERY FORTUNATE
FOR YOU, RAEL.
DON'T YOU DARE DO
ANYTHING LIKE THAT AGAIN.
IT'S CONTEMPTIBLE.
THEN DON'T TORMENT ME.
YOU KNOW HOW I FEEL.
I DON'T CARE WHAT
YOUR FEELINGS ARE.
I DON'T WANT TO KNOW
THAT ASPECT OF IT.
WHAT I DO IS NECESSARY,
AND YOU HAVE NO
RIGHT TO QUESTION IT.
ALLOW ME THE DIGNITY OF
LIKING THE MAN I SELECT.
IS THE TRANSPORTER
REPAIRED?
NO.
I HAVE MORE
WORK TO DO.
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU'D BETTER DO IT?
HE LOVES ME.
I ADORED HIM
WHEN I WAS A CHILD.
I SUPPOSE I STILL DO.
I MUST SAY, YOU BEHAVED
BETTER THAN HE DID.
YES, I HOPE SO.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I SAID I HOPED
I BEHAVED CORRECTLY.
AND NOTHING
BOTHERS YOU NOW?
WHY ARE WE HERE?
OUR LEAVING
WAS DELAYED.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER?
YOU DAMAGED
THE TRANSPORTER.
OH, YES.
THAT WAS WRONG OF ME.
YES, IT CERTAINLY WAS.
BUT WE ARE GOING
TO SCALOS?
DO YOU WANT TO?
OH, YES.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR CREW?
AREN'T YOU WORRIED
ABOUT THEM?
THEY'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
OH.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NOTHING.
YOU'VE COMPLETELY
ACCEPTED THE SITUATION,
HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU EVEN LIKE IT.
AM I BEHAVING INCORRECTLY?
NO.
I LIKED YOU
BETTER BEFORE.
STUBBORN
AND IRRITATING
AND INDEPENDENT,
LIKE RAEL.
THOSE ARE UNDESIRABLE
QUALITIES.
MAYBE THAT'S WHY
I LIKED YOU SO MUCH.
BECAUSE YOU
WERE LIKE HIM.
RAEL?
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT
THE CAPTAIN.
HE'S MADE
THE ADJUSTMENT.
FINISHED.
YES, IT COUNTERACTS
THE SUBSTANCE
MOST EFFECTIVELY.
MOST EFFECTIVELY
UNDER LABORATORY CONDITIONS,
BUT THE QUESTION
IS, WILL IT WORK
IN THE HUMAN BODY?
AND THE SECOND QUESTION
IS, HOW DO WE GET IT
TO THE CAPTAIN?
BY DRINKING
THE SCALOSIAN WATER.
BUT, SPOCK, YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT THAT'LL DO TO
YOU.
IT IS SOMEWHAT...
STIMULATING.
YOU SEEM TO BE MOVING
VERY SLOWLY, DOCTOR.
FASCINATING.
HE'S GONE.
JUST LIKE COMPTON.
[BEEP]
I'VE BEAMED
THE OTHERS DOWN.
IS IT REPAIRED ALREADY?
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
IT WOULD'VE BEEN
AN INTRUSION.
COME UP WHEN YOU WISH.
SIGNAL ME
WHEN YOU'RE READY.
WHERE WILL YOU BE?
IN LIFE SUPPORT.
I HAVE TO ACTIVATE
OUR UNIT.
RAEL, WAIT.
I'M SORRY.
I KNOW.
WELL, COME, CAPTAIN.
IT'S TIME TO LEAVE
YOUR PRETTY SHIP.
[NECKBAND BEEPS]
THE UNIT IS
ACTIVATED, DEELA.
BEAM DOWN AT ONCE.
YOUR CREW WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
YOU SAID SO YOURSELF.
I'M SORRY.
[NECKBAND BEEPS]
HE'S BROKEN AWAY.
HE'S ARMED.
I'M READY FOR HIM.
YOU ARE VERY
CLEVER, CAPTAIN.
YOU TRICKED ME.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN THAT
YOU WOULD NEVER ADJUST.
WHAT SHALL WE
EXPECT FROM YOU NOW?
WE COULD PUT YOU
IN SUSPENDED ANIMATION
UNTIL WE DETERMINE
WHAT TO DO WITH YOU.
YOUR SURVIVAL DOES
NOT DEPEND ON THAT.
NO, IT DOESN'T.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
US TO DO WITH YOU?
DON'T MAKE A GAME
OF IT, CAPTAIN.
WE'VE LOST.
IF I SEND YOU
BACK TO SCALOS,
YOU'D UNDOUBTEDLY
PLAY THE SAME TRICK
ON THE NEXT
SPACESHIP THAT
PASS BY.
THERE WON'T BE ANY OTHERS.
YOU'LL WARN THEM.
YOUR FEDERATION
WILL QUARANTINE
THE ENTIRE AREA.
YES, I SUPPOSE
IT WOULD.
AND WE WILL DIE AND SOLVE
YOUR PROBLEM THAT WAY...
AND OURS.
NOW, WHAT ABOUT
YOUR PROBLEM,
CAPTAIN?
AND YOUR
VULCAN FRIEND?
IF YOU WILL DEVOTE
YOURSELF EXCLUSIVELY
TO THE CONCERNS
OF SCALOS, MADAM,
WE SHALL BE
PLEASED TO REMAIN
AND TAKE CARE
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
YOU COULD STILL FIND LIFE
ON SCALOS VERY PLEASANT.
AND VERY BRIEF.
IT'LL BE JUST
AS BRIEF HERE.
YOU CANNOT GET BACK
TO YOUR OWN LEVEL.
NO ANSWER, CAPTAIN.
DO I DISPLEASE
YOU SO MUCH?
OH, NO.
I CAN THINK OF
NOTHING I'D...
RATHER DO...
THAN STAY WITH YOU.
EXCEPT STAYING ALIVE.
ENERGIZE.
GOODBYE, CAPTAIN.
[TRANSPORTER ENERGIZES]
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
DR. McCOY AND I
HAVE SYNTHESIZED
A POSSIBLE COUNTERAGENT
TO THE SCALOSIAN WATER.
REGRETTABLY, WE DID NOT
HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY
TO TEST IT.
LET'S TEST IT.
NOTHING'S HAPPENING.
YOU DO SEEM TO BE MOVING
VERY SLOWLY, CAPTAIN.
[SLOWED-DOWN VOICE]
MISTER...
SPOCK.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
WHERE THE BLAZES
DID YOU COME FROM?
OUT OF THE NOWHERE,
INTO THE HERE.
AND MR. SPOCK,
IS HE COMING, TOO?
SCOTTY.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5710.9.
MR. SPOCK HAS REMAINED
IN ACCELERATED TIME
SO THAT HE MIGHT
EFFECT REPAIRS TO
THE SHIP MORE RAPIDLY.
[SULU]
SOMEBODY'S REPAIRING
EVERY CONSOLE ON THE SHIP.
[SCOTTY]
THIS PANEL IS
BEING RECIRCUITED
AT INCREDIBLE SPEED.
I THINK WE'VE
LOCATED MR. SPOCK.
LIEUTENANT, ARE YOUR
CIRCUITS CLEARING?
YES, SIR.
CANCEL RED ALERT,
MR. SULU.
AYE, SIR.
OPEN ALL CHANNELS.
CAPTAIN TO CREW,
REPAIRS ARE NOW BEING
EFFECTED BY MR. SPOCK.
THE SHIP WILL RESUME
NORMAL OPERATIONS
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
MR. SPOCK, MY COMPLIMENTS
TO YOUR REPAIR WORK
AND YOURSELF.
THANK YOU,
CAPTAIN.
I FOUND IT
AN ACCELERATING
EXPERIENCE.
YES.
NO MALFUNCTIONS
ANYWHERE?
LIEUTENANT.
OH, I'M SORRY, SIR.
I TOUCHED THE TAPE
BUTTON ACCIDENTALLY.
I'LL TAKE IT OFF.
THAT'S...
NO MALFUNCTION?
NO, SIR.
GOODBYE, DEELA.