CAPTAIN'S LOG--
STARDATE 5121.5.
ORBITING
THE SECOND PLANET IN
THE MINARIAN STAR SYSTEM.
THIS STAR HAS LONG
GIVEN EVIDENCE OF
ENTERING A NOVA PHASE,
AND 6 MONTHS AGO,
A RESEARCH STATION
WAS ESTABLISHED
TO MAKE CLOSE-UP
STUDIES OF THE STAR
AS ITS END APPROACHES.
MINARA IS NOW ENTERING
A CRITICAL PERIOD,
AND THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN ORDERED TO
EVACUATE THE STATION
BEFORE THE PLANET
BECOMES UNINHABITABLE.
YET OUR ATTEMPTS TO
CONTACT THE STATION'S
PERSONNEL
HAVE BEEN,
SO FAR, UNSUCCESSFUL.
DUST. APPARENTLY THESE
INSTRUMENTS HAVE NOT
BEEN RECENTLY USED.
A RECORD TAPE.
MAYBE IT'LL TELL US
SOMETHING
ABOUT THE PERSONNEL
THAT LIVED HERE.
[COMMUNICATOR
BEEPS]
ENTERPRISE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, PLEASE.
KIRK HERE. WHAT
IS IT, ENTERPRISE?
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
OUR INSTRUMENTS HAVE
PICKED UP A GIGANTIC
SOLAR FLARE
WITH VERY HIGH LEVELS OF
COSMIC RAYS ACCOMPANYING IT.
HOW BAD?
AN ENORMOUS ONE.
OUR SENSORS INDICATE
THE COSMIC RAY CONCENTRATION
MEASURES 3.51
ON THE RITTER SCALE.
THAT'LL PLAY THE VERY
DEVIL WITH THE CREW,
AS WELL AS THE SHIP.
AT THAT RATE, IT WILL TAKE
EXACTLY 74.1 SOLAR HOURS
FOR THE STORM TO PASS.
GET THE SHIP OUT OF HERE.
STAY AT MINIMUM DISTANCE
FOR ABSOLUTE SAFETY.
AYE, AYE, SIR. WE'LL
BEAM YOU UP IN--
NEGATIVE. WE'RE
STAYING HERE.
THE ATMOSPHERE
OF THE PLANET
WILL PROTECT US.
GET THAT SHIP
OUT OF HERE,
MR. SCOTT.
VERY WELL, SIR.
SCOTT OUT.
MR. SPOCK, WHAT
ABOUT THAT TAPE?
REMEMBER, CAPTAIN,
WHAT WE SEE ON THIS TAPE
HAPPENED APPROXIMATELY
3 MONTHS AGO.
I DON'T THINK I CAN
STAND ANOTHER WEEK
IN THIS
GODFORSAKEN PLACE.
[RUMBLING]
"IN HIS HAND ARE
THE DEEP PLACES
OF THE EARTH."
PSALM 95, VERSE 4.
LOOKS LIKE
HE WAS LISTENING.
[HIGH-PITCHED SOUND]
[BEEP]
WHO'S OUT THERE?
AAH!
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM?
[HIGH-PITCHED SOUND]
WHERE'S THAT SOUND
COMING FROM?
SPOCK, CAN YOU
PINPOINT IT?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
IT DOESN'T REGISTER.
BONES!
SPOCK!
[RUMBLING]
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
SPOCK...
BONES...
WHERE ARE WE?
EXACTLY 121.32 METERS
BENEATH THE PLANET'S
SURFACE, CAPTAIN.
HOW DID
WE GET HERE?
RESIDUAL
ENERGY READINGS INDICATE
WE WERE BEAMED HERE BY
A MATTER-ENERGY SCRAMBLER,
SIMILAR TO OUR OWN
TRANSPORTER MECHANISM.
THAT'S A NASTY CUT, JIM.
DOES IT HURT?
NO.
CAPTAIN, PICKING UP
A LIFE FORM READING--
BEARING 42 MARK 7.
ONE OF THE MISSING
SCIENTISTS?
NEGATIVE.
ALTHOUGH HUMANOID,
IT IS DEFINITELY
NOT HOMOSAPIENS.
IDENTIFICATION.
IMPOSSIBLE. I CAN MAKE
NO EXACT IDENTIFICATION
OTHER THAN
IT BEING HUMANOID.
LET'S FIND OUT.
PHASERS ON STUN.
APPROACHING
THE LIFE FORM, CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
STILL UNDISTINGUISHABLE.
BE CAREFUL.
WHY, SHE SEEMS
HARMLESS ENOUGH.
THE SAND-BATS
OF MANARK-4
APPEAR TO BE INANIMATE
ROCK CRYSTALS, DOCTOR...
UNTIL THEY ATTACK.
WE'RE NOT GOING
TO HURT YOU.
IS THIS YOUR HOME?
DO YOU LIVE HERE?
WHAT ABOUT IT,
SPOCK? ANALYSIS.
FROM WHAT WE KNOW
OF THE SPECIFIC GRAVITY
AND OTHER ENVIRONMENTAL
FACTORS OF THIS PLANET,
A LIFE FORM SUCH AS HERS
COULD NOT EVOLVE HERE.
ARE YOU RESPONSIBLE
FOR BRINGING US HERE?
DON'T BE AFRAID.
BONES,
WHAT'S WRONG WITH HER?
SHE'S A MUTE, JIM.
NO VOCAL CORDS,
NOT EVEN VESTIGALS.
AND I DON'T THINK
IT'S A PATHOLOGICAL
CONDITION.
EXPLAIN.
SHE APPEARS TO BE
PERFECTLY HEALTHY.
FOR THE OTHER,
HER LACK OF VOCAL CORDS
COULD BE PHYSIOLOGICALLY
NORMAL FOR HER SPECIES,
WHATEVER THAT IS.
A RACE OF MUTES,
LIKE THE CIVILIZATION
ON GAMMA-VERTIS-4.
THAT'S MY
OBSERVATION,
FOR WHATEVER
IT'S WORTH.
WITHOUT SPEECH, HOW IS
SHE GOING TO BE ABLE
TO UNDERSTAND US?
UNLESS SHE'S A TELEPATH.
AN UNLIKELY POSSIBILITY,
CAPTAIN,
SINCE OVER 98% OF THE
KNOWN TELEPATHIC SPECIES
SEND THOUGHTS
AS WELL AS RECEIVE THEM.
SHE'S MADE NO ATTEMPT
TO CONTACT OUR MINDS.
WELL, WE CAN'T KEEP
REFERRING TO HER AS "SHE,"
AS IF SHE WEREN'T HERE.
YOU HAVE ANY IDEAS?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU, BUT I'M
GONNA CALL HER GEM.
GEM, DOCTOR?
WELL, THAT'S BETTER
THAN "HEY, YOU."
I WANT TO KNOW
WHY WE'RE HERE.
WHAT'S GOING ON.
AND SHE KNOWS.
I'M CAPTAIN--
WE ARE AWARE
OF YOUR IDENTITY,
CAPTAIN.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY DID YOU
BRING US HERE?
WE ARE VIANS.
DO NOT INTERFERE.
WHAT DO YOU INTEND
TO DO WITH US?
DELAY US NO LONGER.
WE COME--
SINCE YOU ALREADY
KNOW WHO WE ARE,
YOU MUST ALSO KNOW
THAT WE COME IN PEACE.
OUR PRIME DIRECTIVE
SPECIFICALLY
PROHIBITS US FROM
ANY INTERFERENCE--
I...CAN'T...
SEEM...TO STAND UP.
DON'T...FIGHT...
THE FORCE FIELD.
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT IT THAT
UPSETS THE...
BODY METABOLISM.
NOT QUITE, DOCTOR.
THE FIELD DRAWS ITS
ENERGY FROM YOUR BODIES.
THE MORE YOU RESIST,
THE STRONGER
THE FORCE FIELD BECOMES.
AH.
SUFFICIENT.
SPOCK...
THERE MUST BE AN EXIT
OTHER THAN
THE ONE WE JUST SAW.
CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
YOU FEEL
ALL RIGHT, JIM?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
THEY MAY HAVE HURT HER.
DID THEY HURT YOU?
THE PAIN IS GONE.
SHE TOUCHED MY HEAD
AND THE PAIN IS GONE.
THE WOUND IS
COMPLETELY HEALED.
IT FITS, JIM.
SHE MUST BE AN EMPATH.
HER NERVOUS SYSTEM
IS SO SENSITIVE,
HIGHLY RESPONSIVE,
THAT SHE CAN ACTUALLY
FEEL OUR EMOTIONAL
AND PHYSICAL REACTIONS.
THEY BECOME PART OF HER.
THANK YOU.
CAPTAIN,
IN THIS DIRECTION,
MY TRICORDER
IS NOW PICKING UP
A SUBSTANTIAL
COLLECTION
OF OBJECTS.
DETAILS.
ELECTRONICALLY
SOPHISTICATED
DEVICES.
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY MY TRICORDER
PREVIOUSLY GAVE
NO INDICATION OF
THEM BEING OUT THERE.
WELL, THEY'RE THERE NOW.
LET'S GO CHECK THEM OUT.
STAYING HERE ALONE
COULD BE DANGEROUS.
COME WITH US.
FASCINATING.
LOOK AT THIS STUFF.
BONES...
SPOCK, COME HERE.
JIM, SPOCK.
YOU ARE ON SCHEDULE.
SOME FURTHER SIMPLE
TESTS ARE NECESSARY.
WE'VE JUST SEEN THE RESULTS
OF SOME OF YOUR TESTS.
I FOUND OUR
MISSING MEN...DEAD.
ANOTHER ONE
OF YOUR EXPERIMENTS?
YOU'RE WRONG.
THEIR OWN IMPERFECTIONS
KILLED THEM.
THEY WERE NOT FIT SUBJECTS.
COME.
TIME IS SHORT.
YES. YOUR TIME
IS RUNNING OUT.
THIS SUN IS
ABOUT TO NOVA.
WHEN IT DOES,
IT'LL DESTROY YOU,
THIS PLANET,
AND THIS INSANE
TORTURE CHAMBER.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
READINGS INDICATE THE
PASSAGE TO THE SURFACE
LIES IN THIS DIRECTION.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE,
COME IN.
OUT OF RANGE.
READINGS, MR. SPOCK.
THE RESEARCH STATION
6 KILOMETERS
IN THAT DIRECTION,
CAPTAIN.
LET'S GET THERE
AS FAST AS WE CAN.
IF THE ENTERPRISE
HAS A SEARCH PARTY,
IT'LL BE THERE.
SPOCK!
MUCH FURTHER?
JUST AHEAD.
HEY, JIM, LOOK.
SCOTTY AND
A SEARCH PARTY.
-SCOTTY!
STAY THERE!
COME ON!
WE'RE COMING!
KEEP GOING.
THEIR WILL
TO SURVIVE IS GREAT.
THEY LOVE LIFE GREATLY
TO STRUGGLE SO.
THE PRIME INGREDIENT.
WHERE DID THEY GO?
I BELIEVE THEY
WERE NEVER ACTUALLY
PRESENT, DOCTOR.
IT WAS A MIRAGE.
WHERE'S KIRK?
JIM.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
WHERE'S SCOTTY?
CAPTAIN,
IT WAS A MIRAGE.
CAPTAIN KIRK!
WE HAVE DECIDED
THAT ONE SPECIMEN
WILL BE SUFFICIENT.
YOU WILL
COME WITH US.
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
WE HAVE NO
INTEREST IN THEM.
THEY MAY GO.
VERY WELL.
YOU CAN'T GO BACK THERE.
YOU'LL END UP LIKE
THE OTHER TWO.
CAPTAIN, I REQUEST
PERMISSION TO BE
ALLOWED TO--
-DENIED!
-BUT, CAPTAIN--
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO MY MEN?!
THEY ARE SAFE.
ONE SPECIMEN!
YOU SAID ONE SPECIMEN!
WHAT HAPPENED
TO MY MEN?
INDEED, THE PRIME
INGREDIENT.
WHERE ARE THEY?
TELL ME!
YOU SAID YOU'D
LET THEM GO!
MR. SULU,
WILL YOU GIVE US
AN ESTIMATE ON
HOW MUCH LONGER
WE'LL HAVE UNTIL THOSE
SOLAR FLARES SUBSIDE?
AYE, SIR.
READINGS
NOW INDICATE 2.721
ON THE RITTER SCALE.
AT THE PRESENT
RATE OF DECREASE,
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT
AT LEAST 17 HOURS MORE
BEFORE WE
CAN EVEN ATTEMPT
TO ENTER ORBIT.
AYE.
WELL, AS LONG AS
WE'RE STUCK OUT HERE,
WE MIGHT AS WELL RELAX
UNTIL THE STORM PASSES.
THE STORM'S ALREADY
LASTED 4 HOURS LONGER
THAN WE'VE ANTICIPATED.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
OUR LANDING PARTY
COULD BE IN ANY DANGER?
THAT'S NOT LIKELY.
THE PLANET'S ATMOSPHERE
WILL GIVE THEM
AMPLE PROTECTION.
AND IF I KNOW CAPTAIN KIRK,
HE'LL BE MORE
WORRIED ABOUT US
THAN WE ARE ABOUT HIM.
AAH!
WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT TO KNOW?
WE SEEK
NO INFORMATION
AS YOU MEAN.
YOUR CIVILIZATION
IS YET TOO IMMATURE
TO HAVE KNOWLEDGE
OF VALUE TO US.
YOU DON'T NEED ANY
KNOWLEDGE FROM US,
YET YOU'RE WILLING
TO KILL FOR IT.
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED
TO LINKE AND OZABA?
WE DID NOT KILL THEM.
THEIR OWN
FEARS KILLED THEM.
WELL, WHAT DID YOU
EXPECT FROM THEM?
AND WHAT DO YOU
WANT FROM ME?
WE'VE ALREADY
OBSERVED THE INTENSITY
OF YOUR PASSIONS,
AND GAUGED
YOUR CAPACITY
TO LOVE OTHERS.
NOW WE WANT YOU
TO REVEAL TO US
YOUR COURAGE
AND STRENGTH OF WILL.
WHY?
WHAT IS IT
YOU HOPE TO PROVE?
IF MY DEATH IS
TO HAVE ANY MEANING,
AT LEAST TELL ME
WHAT I'M DYING FOR.
IF YOU LIVE,
YOU WILL HAVE YOUR ANSWER.
AAH!
UHH!
COME ON, SPOCK,
THE PASSAGEWAY
WAS THERE BEFORE.
IT'S GOT TO BE THERE.
DOCTOR,
I AM UNABLE TO LOCK IN
ON THE PREVIOUS READINGS.
I CAN FIND
NO EXIT OUT OF HERE.
CAPTAIN!
JIM, WHAT IS IT?
WHAT HAVE THEY DONE TO YOU?
HELP HIM! DON'T BE
AFRAID TO HELP HIM.
GEM.
YOU LIE STILL.
I'LL CHECK HER OUT
RIGHT AWAY.
WILL SHE LIVE?
SHE SEEMS
FINE NOW.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN
WHAT HAPPENED?
COMPLETE EMPATHY.
SHE MUST BE A TOTALLY
FUNCTIONAL EMPATH.
HER NERVOUS SYSTEM
ACTUALLY CONNECTED
TO YOURS
TO COUNTERACT THE WORST
OF YOUR SYMPTOMS.
AND WITH HER STRENGTH,
SHE VIRTUALLY
SUSTAINED YOUR BODY'S
PHYSIOLOGICAL REACTIONS.
BUT SHE WEAKENED.
I COULD FEEL IT.
IS HER LIFE IN DANGER?
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
TO SAY YET,
BUT SUPPLYING YOUR BODY
WITH LIFE SUPPORT
DID DRAIN HER.
HER WITHDRAWAL SEEMED
TO SUGGEST THE FEAR
OF DEATH, DOCTOR.
ONLY YOUR URGING HER ON
CAUSED HER TO CONTINUE.
THAT'S TRUE. FEAR
WOULD NATURALLY BE
A FIRST REACTION.
PERHAPS SHE DOESN'T
KNOW OUR CAPTAIN
WELL ENOUGH YET
TO OFFER UP
HER LIFE FOR HIM.
COULD THE STRAIN
REALLY HAVE KILLED HER?
OH, YES. HOWEVER, I WOULD
ASSUME THAT HER INSTINCT
FOR SELF-PRESERVATION
WOULD TAKE OVER
TO PREVENT IT.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
I'M...
TIRED.
CAN YOU RECALL
WHAT HAPPENED, CAPTAIN?
I REMEMBER
THE LABORATORY,
AND THEY WANTED
TO KNOW SOMETHING.
BUT I...
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
TAKE IT EASY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH ME?
YOU HAVE ALL THE
SYMPTOMS OF THE BENDS.
NITROGEN BUBBLES
IN YOUR BLOOD
CAUSED THE PAIN.
NOW, HOW WOULD ONE
GET THE BENDS DOWN HERE?
YOU'LL HAVE
TO ASK THE VIANS.
WILL I LIVE?
WELL, YOU COULD USE
SOME TIME IN
A DECOMPRESSION CHAMBER.
BUT OTHERWISE,
I'D SAY YOUR RECOVERY
IS JUST ABOUT MIRACULOUS.
I WISH I COULD
TAKE THE CREDIT FOR IT,
BUT SHE DID THE WORK.
CAPTAIN, I NOTED THAT
A LIGHT PRECEDED YOU
AT THE MOMENT
YOU WERE RETURNED HERE
FROM THE VIANS' LABORATORY.
SPOCK,
WHY DO YOU HAVE TO
GET SO ANALYTICAL--
HE'S RIGHT. CONTINUE.
I CONCLUDE THAT SUCH
A LIGHT IS AN ENERGY
TRANSFER POINT
LINKING THIS DEVICE
TO THE POWER SOURCE.
CAN YOU TAP INTO IT?
IF I CAN DETERMINE
THE FREQUENCY AT WHICH
THIS DEVICE OPERATES,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO CAUSE
IT TO FUNCTION FOR US.
AND GET US OUT OF HERE
THE SAME WAY
THEY BROUGHT US IN.
I WOULD SAY SO.
THEN I WOULD SAY PROCEED.
YOU ARE CALLED CAPTAIN.
YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE LIVES OF YOUR CREW.
IS THIS CORRECT?
IT IS.
WE FIND IT NECESSARY
TO HAVE THE COOPERATION
OF ONE OF YOUR MEN
IN OUR EFFORTS.
WE WILL NOT COOPERATE.
WHEN WE RESUME
OUR INTERROGATIONS,
YOU WILL DECIDE WHICH OF
YOUR MEN WE SHALL USE.
IT IS ESSENTIAL.
THERE'S AN 87% CHANCE
THAT THE DOCTOR WILL DIE,
AND WHILE COMMANDER SPOCK'S
LIFE IS NOT IN DANGER,
THE POSSIBILITY IS 93%
THAT HE WILL SUFFER
BRAIN DAMAGE
RESULTING IN
PERMANENT INSANITY.
HOW'S IT COMING, SPOCK?
I DO NOT KNOW,
CAPTAIN.
I BEGIN
TO UNDERSTAND
ITS OPERATING
PRINCIPLES,
BUT THAT IS ALL.
SPOCK, IT WON'T BE TOO LONG
BEFORE THE VIANS COME BACK.
YOU BETTER FIND OUT
HOW THAT THING WORKS,
AND SOON.
TAKE IT EASY, BONES.
MEN WEREN'T INTENDED TO LIVE
THIS FAR UNDERGROUND.
IT'S JUST NOT NATURAL.
AND SPACE TRAVEL IS?
SOME MEN SPEND
THE MAJORITY
OF THEIR LIVES
IN MINES BENEATH
THE SURFACE.
I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT A COAL MINER.
I'VE RECORDED MY PRINCIPLES
AND THEORIES
ON THE TRICORDER, DOCTOR.
SHOULD THE VIANS RETURN,
THERE'S SUFFICIENT DATA
FOR YOU AND THE CAPTAIN
TO COMPLETE
THE ADJUSTMENTS.
I'M NOT A MECHANIC.
I COULDN'T GET
THAT THING TO WORK
NO MATTER HOW MANY NOTES
YOU LEFT.
POSSIBLY NOT,
BUT YOU AND
THE CAPTAIN TOGETHER
WILL BE ABLE TO DO SO.
IN ANY CASE, SPOCK,
YOU'RE THE LOGICAL ONE
TO LEAVE WITH
THE CAPTAIN.
THE DECISION IS MINE.
IF THERE ARE
ANY DECISIONS
TO BE MADE,
I'LL MAKE THEM.
IF AND WHEN
IT BECOMES NECESSARY.
WHAT--
I DON'T NEED ANY.
I'M STILL CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER
ON THE ENTERPRISE.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT YOU NEED
AND WHEN YOU NEED IT.
WOULD YOU RATHER
HAVE THE BENDS?
THAT'S IT.
JUST LIE DOWN AND RELAX.
HOW LONG WILL HE
BE ASLEEP, DOCTOR?
BETWEEN
THE EMOTIONAL STRAIN
AND THE ATTACK
OF BENDS,
HE'S IN PRETTY
BAD SHAPE.
I'M NOT CRITICIZING
YOUR ACTION, DOCTOR.
ON THE CONTRARY,
I'M QUITE GRATEFUL FOR IT.
THE CAPTAIN WILL BE
SPARED THE STRAIN
OF MAKING SO DIFFICULT
A DECISION.
YOU HAVE SIMPLIFIED
THE SITUATION CONSIDERABLY.
HOW?
WHILE THE CAPTAIN
IS ASLEEP,
I AM IN COMMAND.
WHEN THE VIANS RETURN,
I SHALL GO WITH THEM.
YOU MEAN IF I HADN'T
GIVEN HIM THAT SHOT--
PRECISELY.
THE CHOICE WOULD HAVE
BEEN THE CAPTAIN'S.
NOW IT IS MINE.
YOUR ACTION
IS HIGHLY UNETHICAL.
MY DECISION...STANDS.
NOT THIS TIME, SPOCK.
THE CHOICE HAS BEEN MADE.
THEY'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
COME, THEN.
DOCTOR,
PLEASE UNDERSTAND
THAT IF THERE WAS
ANY OTHER WAY
TO ACCOMPLISH
OUR PURPOSE...
GET ON WITH IT.
WHY DID YOU
LET HIM DO IT?
I WAS CONVINCED IN THE SAME
WAY YOU WERE, CAPTAIN,
BY THE GOOD DOCTOR'S HYPO.
ANYTHING?
HMM.
A MOST UNUSUAL DEVICE.
IT IS A CONTROL UNIT,
BUT NOT A CONTROL MECHANISM.
IN FACT, IT IS NOT
A MECHANICAL DEVICE.
WHAT EXACTLY IS IT?
THIS CONTROL IS ATTUNED
TO ONE ELECTRICAL PATTERN
OF ENERGY,
THE PATTERN PRODUCED
BY THE MENTAL IMPULSES
OF THE PERSON
WHO POSSESSES IT.
IT IS ACTIVATED SOLELY
BY MENTAL COMMANDS.
CAN YOU ADAPT IT,
RE-ATTUNE IT TO FIT
OUR BRAIN PATTERN?
I SHALL ATTEMPT TO DO SO.
HOWEVER, IT IS NOT POSSIBLE
TO ADJUST THE CONTROL
TO FIT MORE THAN
ONE PATTERN AT A TIME.
I AM, OF COURSE, MOST FAMILIAR
WITH MY OWN PATTERN,
THEREFORE, WITH YOUR
PERMISSION, I--
DO WHATEVER YOU HAVE TO
TO MAKE IT WORK, SPOCK.
WHAT DISTURBS ME
IS WHY THE VIANS
LET US KEEP IT.
FASCINATING.
THEY MUST HAVE KNOWN
WE WERE CAPABLE OF
COMPREHENDING THIS CONTROL
AND MAKING USE OF IT.
AND THAT WE WOULD
USE IT TO ESCAPE.
THE ONLY LOGICAL ASSUMPTION
IS THAT THEY WISH
TO LET US GO.
AND THEY KEEP McCOY.
THAT IS EVIDENTLY
THEIR INTENTION, CAPTAIN.
SOMEHOW,
YOU'RE THE CRUX,
THE FOCAL POINT
OF ALL THIS.
EVEN BEFORE WE GOT HERE,
SHE WAS A PRISONER.
THEY DIDN'T HURT HER
AND THEY DIDN'T EVEN
THREATEN HER.
INDEED. THE FACTS
WOULD INDICATE
THAT SHE IS ESSENTIAL
TO THEIR PURPOSE.
YES, THERE IS A PURPOSE,
BUT WHAT IS IT?
HAS ALL THE PAIN
AND TERROR HAPPENED
OR BEEN MADE
TO HAPPEN...
FOR YOU?
COMPLETED, CAPTAIN.
THE ADJUSTMENTS
ARE DELICATE.
THEY MAY NOT SURVIVE MORE
THAN EVEN ONE USE.
HOWEVER, THERE SHOULD BE
SUFFICIENT ENERGY
TO TRANSFER US
TO THE ENTERPRISE.
WILL IT TAKE US
TO McCOY?
IF YOU SO DESIRE.
THE BEST DEFENSE
IS A STRONG OFFENSE,
AND I INTEND TO START
OFFENDING RIGHT NOW.
AIM FOR THE LAB.
BONES.
SPOCK.
GET HIM DOWN.
HIS WRISTS.
HIS PULSE IS ALMOST GONE.
HOW IS HE?
SEVERE HEART DAMAGE.
SIGNS OF CONGESTION
IN BOTH LUNGS.
EVIDENCE OF MASSIVE
CIRCULATORY COLLAPSE.
[GROANS]
DON'T TALK.
DON'T SPEAK.
TAKE IT EASY
UNTIL WE GET YOU
BACK TO THE SHIP.
WHAT IS IT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
HE'S DYING, JIM.
WE CAN MAKE HIM
COMFORTABLE,
BUT THAT IS ALL.
YOU DON'T KNOW.
YOU'RE NOT A DOCTOR.
[MUTTERING]
INTERNAL INJURIES.
BLEEDING IN THE CHEST
AND ABDOMEN.
HEMORRHAGE OF THE SPLEEN
AND LIVER.
70% KIDNEY FAILURE.
HE'S RIGHT, JIM.
BEING A DOCTOR
HAS ITS DRAWBACKS. I...
ALWAYS WONDERED WHY I--
[COUGHING]
[COUGHING AND GASPING]
THANKS.
HOW LONG?
IT COULD HAPPEN
ANYTIME.
THE CORRECT MEDICAL PHRASE,
EH, SPOCK?
[COUGHING]
YOU'VE GOT A...
GOOD BEDSIDE MANNER,
SPOCK.
CAN'T WE DO SOMETHING?
I'M AFRAID NOT.
GEM MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP HIM
THE WAY SHE HELPED ME,
BUT COULD HIS NEARNESS
TO DEATH ALSO KILL HER?
UNCERTAIN, CAPTAIN.
DR. McCOY'S ANALYSIS
OF HER REACTION
ASSUMES THAT HER INSTINCT
FOR SELF-PRESERVATION
WOULD PREVENT IT.
HOWEVER, WE CANNOT
BE POSITIVE.
IF SHE COULD JUST
STRENGTHEN HIM
AND KEEP HIM
FROM SINKING FURTHER
INTO DEATH,
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SAVE HIM.
NO INTERFERENCE
WILL BE PERMITTED.
SHE COULD SAVE
HIS LIFE.
LET US HELP HER
TO GO TO HIM.
SHE MUST NOT BE
URGED OR FORCED
TO TAKE ACTION.
ALL MUST PROCEED
WITHOUT
INTERFERENCE.
THE PURPOSE
THAT BROUGHT US
TOGETHER--
WHAT PURPOSE CAN
ALL THIS SERVE,
EXCEPT THE FULFILLMENT
OF SOME NEED OF YOURS?
WE HAVE BUT ONE NEED
LEFT IN LIFE--
AND THAT IS
TO SEE THE COMPLETION
OF THE FINAL MOMENT
OF OUR TEST.
BE PATIENT.
PATIENT? OUR FRIEND
IS DYING.
PERHAPS.
WHAT PURPOSE CAN BE SERVED
BY THE DEATH OF OUR FRIEND
EXCEPT TO BRING YOU PLEASURE?
SURELY BEINGS AS ADVANCED
AS YOURSELVES
KNOW THAT YOUR STAR SYSTEM
WILL SOON BE EXTINCT.
YOUR SUN WILL NOVA.
WE KNOW.
THEN YOU ALSO KNOW
THAT THE MILLIONS
OF INHABITANTS
ON ITS PLANETS ARE DOOMED.
THAT IS WHY WE ARE HERE.
THIS ARENA OF DEATH
THAT YOU HAVE DEVISED
FOR YOUR PLEASURE--
WILL IT PREVENT
THIS CATASTROPHE?
NO, IT WILL NOT,
BUT IT MAY SAVE
GEM'S PLANET.
OF ALL THE PLANETS
OF MINARA,
WE HAVE THE POWER
TO TRANSPORT
THE INHABITANTS OF
ONLY ONE TO SAFETY.
IF GEM'S PLANET
IS THE ONE THAT
WILL BE SAVED,
WE MUST
MAKE CERTAIN
BEYOND ANY DOUBT
WHATSOEVER
THEY ARE WORTHY
OF SURVIVAL.
HOW WILL THE DEATH
OF OUR FRIEND
SERVE THIS PURPOSE?
HIS DEATH
WILL NOT SERVE IT,
BUT HER WILLINGNESS TO GIVE
HER LIFE FOR HIM WILL.
YOU WERE HER TEACHERS.
WE WERE?
WHAT COULD SHE
LEARN FROM US?
YOUR WILL TO SURVIVE.
YOUR LOVE OF LIFE.
YOUR PASSION TO KNOW.
THEY ARE RECORDED
IN HER BEING.
HER PLANET WILL
BE FORTUNATE.
EACH OF YOU WAS WILLING
TO GIVE HIS LIFE
FOR THE OTHERS.
WE MUST NOW FIND OUT
WHETHER THAT INSTINCT
HAS BEEN TRANSMITTED
TO GEM.
[RUMBLING]
TIME GROWS SHORT.
YOU WERE CORRECT,
CAPTAIN.
EVERYTHING THAT
HAS OCCURRED HERE
HAS BEEN CAUSED
TO HAPPEN BY THEM.
THIS HAS ALL BEEN
A GREAT LABORATORY,
AND WE HAVE BEEN
THE SUBJECTS OF THE TEST.
NO.
WE ONLY CREATED
THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
THAT WAS NECESSARY.
YOUR ACTIONS
WERE SPONTANEOUS.
EVERYTHING THAT IS
TRUEST AND BEST
IN ALL SPECIES OF BEINGS
HAS BEEN REVEALED BY YOU.
THOSE ARE THE QUALITIES
THAT MAKE A CIVILIZATION
WORTHY TO SURVIVE.
BEHOLD.
THAT IS MOST
SIGNIFICANT.
AN INSTINCT
NEW TO THE ESSENCE
OF HER BEING
IS GENERATING.
COMPASSION FOR ANOTHER
IS BECOMING PART OF HER
FUNCTIONING LIFE SYSTEM.
SHE IS AFRAID.
SHE'S SAVING HERSELF.
SHE DOES NOT YET
HAVE THE INSTINCT
TO SAVE HER PEOPLE.
WE HAVE FAILED.
NO.
NO, NOT YET.
CAPTAIN,
DR. McCOY'S LIFE
IS NOT SOLELY
DEPENDENT ON GEM.
THE VIANS, TOO,
MUST BE CAPABLE
OF SAVING HIS LIFE.
TRUE.
THEN YOU CANNOT
LET HIM DIE.
HIS DEATH IS NOT
IMPORTANT.
WE MUST WAIT TO SEE
WHETHER HER INSTINCT
FOR SELF-SACRIFICE
HAS BECOME STRONGER
THAN HER INSTINCT
FOR SELF-PRESERVATION.
[COUGHING]
DON'T TOUCH ME.
STAY AWAY.
JIM.
SPOCK.
ARE YOU HERE?
YES, BONES.
DON'T LET HER TOUCH ME.
SHE'LL DIE.
JIM...
I CAN'T DESTROY LIFE,
EVEN IF IT'S
TO SAVE MY OWN.
I CAN'T. NOW, YOU KNOW THAT.
I CAN'T LET YOU DO IT.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
THE INTENSITY
OF EMOTION
IS DRAINING US
AND BUILDING UP
THE FORCE FIELD.
YES, I KNOW.
IT DRAWS ITS ENERGY
FROM US, CAPTAIN.
IN SPITE OF
WHAT WE SEE,
ALL EMOTION
MUST BE SUPPRESSED.
THAT MIGHT WEAKEN
THE FIELD.
I'LL TRY.
YES.
SPOCK.
YOU CANNOT USE OUR POWERS
TO CHANGE WHAT IS HAPPENING.
YOU MUST SAVE THE LIFE
OF OUR FRIEND.
NO.
WE WILL NOT.
HER INSTINCT MUST BE
DEVELOPED TO THE FULLEST.
THE TEST MUST BE COMPLETE.
IT IS COMPLETE.
GEM HAS EARNED
THE RIGHT OF SURVIVAL
FOR HER PLANET.
SHE OFFERED HER LIFE.
TO OFFER IS NOT
PROOF ENOUGH.
IF DEATH IS ALL
YOU UNDERSTAND...
HERE ARE 4 LIVES
FOR YOU.
WE WILL NOT LEAVE
OUR FRIEND.
YOU'VE LOST THE CAPACITY
TO FEEL THE EMOTIONS
YOU BROUGHT GEM HERE
TO EXPERIENCE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT IT IS TO LIVE.
LOVE AND COMPASSION
ARE DEAD IN YOU.
YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT INTELLECT.
FAREWELL.
STRANGE.
WHAT IS PUZZLING YOU,
CAPTAIN?
I'M NOT PUZZLED,
MR. SPOCK. I AM...
AWED.
I'M WITH YOU,
CAPTAIN.
SHE AWED ME.
NO, NO. I WASN'T
THINKING OF GEM.
I WAS THINKING
OF THAT FANTASTIC
ELEMENT OF CHANCE
THAT OUT IN LIMITLESS SPACE
WE SHOULD COME TOGETHER
WITH GEM.
CAPTAIN,
THE ELEMENT OF CHANCE
CAN VIRTUALLY BE ELIMINATED
BY A CIVILIZATION
AS ADVANCED AS THE VIANS.
NOT TO DISPUTE
YOUR COMPUTER,
MR. SPOCK,
BUT FROM WHAT LITTLE
YOU'VE TOLD ME,
I WOULD SAY THAT
SHE WAS A PEARL
OF GREAT PRICE.
WHAT, SCOTT?
DO YOU NOT KNOW
THE STORY OF
THE MERCHANT?
THE MERCHANT.
WHO, WHEN HE
FOUND ONE PEARL
OF GREAT PRICE,
WENT AND SOLD
ALL THAT HE HAD
AND BOUGHT IT.
YES, SHE WAS ALL THAT.
BUT WHETHER THE VIANS
BOUGHT HER OR FOUND HER
MAKES LITTLE DIFFERENCE.
SHE WAS OF GREAT VALUE.
WELL, PERSONALLY,
I FIND IT FASCINATING
THAT WITH ALL THEIR
SCIENTIFIC KNOWLEDGE
AND ADVANCES,
THAT IT WAS GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED HUMAN EMOTION
THAT THEY VALUED THE MOST.
PERHAPS THE VULCANS
SHOULD HEAR
ABOUT THIS.
MR. SPOCK, CAN YOU BE
PREVAILED UPON
TO BRING THEM THE NEWS?
POSSIBLY, CAPTAIN.
I SHALL CERTAINLY
GIVE THE THOUGHT
ALL THE CONSIDERATION
IT IS DUE.
MR. SULU,
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 2.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
WARP FACTOR 2.