CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 4372.5.
ON A TOP-SECRET
DIPLOMATIC MISSION,
THE ENTERPRISE HAS ENTERED
THE TELLUN STAR SYSTEM.
MAINTAINING
COMMUNICATIONS BLACKOUT,
WE HAVE TAKEN ABOARD PETRI,
AMBASSADOR FROM TROYIUS,
THE OUTER PLANET,
AND ARE NOW APPROACHING
THE INNER PLANET, ELAS.
SOME DESKBOUND
STARFLEET BUREAUCRAT
CUT THESE
CLOAK-AND-DAGGER ORDERS.
AYE, BUT WHY
THE SECRECY?
THIS STAR SYSTEM'S UNDER
FEDERATION CONTROL.
IT'S IN A BORDER AREA,
MR. SCOTT.
THE KLINGONS ALSO
CLAIM JURISDICTION.
FROM WHAT I'VE SEEN,
IT'S NOT WORTH
FIGHTING ABOUT.
WHY ARE WE HERE, CAPTAIN?
MY ORDERS ARE TO COOPERATE
WITH AMBASSADOR PETRI
IN ALL MATTERS PERTAINING
TO HIS MISSION HERE.
Uhura: BRIDGE
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
SCOTTY.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT?
CAPTAIN,
I HAVE A SIGNAL
FROM THE ELASIANS.
THEY'RE READY
TO BEAM ABOARD,
AND THEY DEMAND
AN EXPLANATION
FOR THE DELAY.
DEMAND? WHAT DELAY?
ALL RIGHT, BEAM THEM ABOARD.
SOUNDS TYPICAL
OF THE ELASIANS.
THE SCIENTISTS WHO MADE
THE INITIAL INVESTIGATION
REPORTED THE MEN
WERE VICIOUS AND ARROGANT.
OH, THAT'S JUST
THE NEGATIVE PART,
MR. SPOCK.
I'VE BEEN
OVER THOSE RECORDS.
NOW, THE WOMEN,
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO HAVE
A KIND OF SUBTLE,
MYSTICAL POWER
THAT DRIVES MEN WILD.
AMBASSADOR PETRI,
WOULD YOU DROP
ALL THIS NONSENSE
AND TELL ME
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT?
THAT MUST WAIT UNTIL
THE DOHLMAN IS ABOARD.
THE DOHLMAN?
WHAT THE DEVIL'S A DOHLMAN?
THE THING MOST FEARED
AND HATED BY MY PEOPLE.
OUR MOST DEADLY ENEMY.
[TRANSPORTER BEAM]
WELCOME.
I AM PETRI,
AMBASSADOR OF TROYIUS.
I'M CAPTAIN KIRK.
THIS SHIP
IS UNDER MY COMMAND.
THERE'S A TROYIAN HERE.
I MUST KNOW
THAT ALL IS SECURE
BEFORE THE DOHLMAN
IS BROUGHT ON BOARD.
THIS SHIP IS SECURE...
AND WE'RE PREPARED
FOR ANY HOSTILE ACTION.
ENERGIZE.
DO HONOR TO
THE DOHLMAN OF ELAS.
GLORY TO ELAAN,
DOHLMAN OF ELAS.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
YOU MAY STAND.
BODY ARMOR.
NUCLEAR WEAPONS.
NOT WITHOUT PRECEDENT,
CAPTAIN.
REMEMBER THAT--
PERMISSION TO SPEAK
WAS NOT GIVEN.
YOU RULE THIS SHIP?
I AM
THE FIRST OFFICER.
THIS IS
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
YOUR GLORY, I AM PETRI.
IN THE NAME OF MY PEOPLE--
YOUR MISSION
IS KNOWN TO US.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
YOU HAVE NOW PERMISSION
TO SHOW US
TO OUR QUARTERS.
WELL, NOW,
JUST A MOMENT.
THERE'S GOING
TO HAVE TO BE
SOME KIND OF UNDERSTANDING--
PLEASE...
MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK
WILL SHOW YOU
TO YOUR QUARTERS.
AMBASSADOR, IF I
MIGHT SPEAK TO YOU.
Elaan: YOU HAVE NOT
BEEN DISMISSED.
MAY I HAVE
YOUR PERMISSION TO GO?
YOU ARE NOW DISMISSED.
WHY, THANK YOU.
AMBASSADOR.
AMBASSADOR,
I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU TOLD ME
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THAT...CREATURE,
ELAAN,
IS TO BE THE WIFE
OF OUR RULER--
TO BRING PEACE.
OUR TWO WARRING PLANETS
NOW POSSESS
THE CAPABILITY
OF MUTUAL DESTRUCTION.
SOME METHOD
OF COEXISTENCE
MUST BE FOUND.
I SEE.
SO WE GO BACK
TO TROYIUS.
YES. AH,
BUT SLOWLY, CAPTAIN.
I WILL NEED TIME.
BEFORE WE REACH THERE,
SHE MUST BE TAUGHT
CIVILIZED MANNERS.
IN HER
PRESENT CONDITION,
MY PEOPLE WOULD
NEVER ACCEPT HER.
AND YOU ARE TO BE
HER TEACHER?
THOSE ARE MY ORDERS.
I MUST ASK
YOU AND YOUR CREW
TO RESPECT,
OR AT LEAST TOLERATE
THEIR ARROGANCE.
FRICTION MUST BE KEPT
AT A MINIMUM.
YES,
THAT I CAN UNDERSTAND.
ANOTHER THING
YOU SHOULD UNDERSTAND,
CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE AS MUCH
AT STAKE AS I HAVE.
YOUR SUPERIORS HAVE
MADE THE STATEMENT
THAT FAILURE
OF THIS MISSION
WOULD BE AS CATASTROPHIC
FOR FEDERATION PLANNING
AS IT WOULD BE
FOR OUR TWO PLANETS.
TO GAIN PEACE
AT THE PRICE
OF ACCEPTING
SUCH A QUEEN
IS NO VICTORY.
[SIGHS]
I WILL TAKE HER
THE OFFICIAL GIFTS
I BEAR.
PERHAPS THAT
WILL SOFTEN HER MOOD.
MR. CHEKOV,
LAY IN A COURSE FOR TROYIUS.
MR. SULU, IMPULSE DRIVE,
SPEED FACTOR .037.
IMPULSE DRIVE,
CAPTAIN?
YES, THAT'S CORRECT,
MR. SULU.
SUBLIGHT FACTOR .037.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN...
YOU'LL NOT BE USING
THE WARP DRIVE?
ALL THE WAY ON IMPULSE?
THAT'LL TAKE
A GREAT DEAL OF TIME.
YOU IN A HURRY,
MR. SCOTT?
NO.
CAPTAIN, THE DOHLMAN
IS DISSATISFIED
WITH THE QUARTERS
PROVIDED.
AH.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THEM, MR. SPOCK?
I DO NOT KNOW,
BUT ALL THE ELASIANS
SEEM MOST IRRATIONAL.
I GAVE UP MY QUARTERS--
YES, I APPRECIATE
YOUR SACRIFICE,
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
I'LL TALK TO HER
MYSELF.
SWINE!
TAKE BACK YOUR GIFTS!
YOUR GLORY...
THESE ARE
YOUR WEDDING SLIPPERS.
YOUR RULER CANNOT
BUY THE FAVORS
OF THE DOHLMAN
OF ELAS.
THIS...THIS IS
YOUR WEDDING DRESS,
A GIFT FROM
THE BRIDEGROOM'S MOTHER.
I WANT NOTHING OF HIS!
THIS...THIS IS THE MOST
PRIZED OF ROYAL JEWELS,
FOR YOUR LOVELY NECK.
I WOULD STRANGLE
IF I WAS TO PUT THE GIFT
OF A TROYIAN DOG
AROUND MY NECK.
KRYTON,
BY WHOSE PERMISSION
DID HE ENTER?
HE CAME IN ANSWER
TO YOUR SUMMONS.
I UNDERSTAND
YOU'RE NOT HAPPY
WITH YOUR QUARTERS.
QUARTERS?!
[GLASS BREAKS]
YES, NOT HAPPY...AT ALL.
AM I A SOFT TROYIAN FAWN
TO NEED PILLOWS
TO SIT ON?
AND THESE RIDICULOUS
FEMALE TRAPPINGS.
THEY ARE AN OFFENSE
TO MY EYES.
MY COMMUNICATIONS
OFFICER
GENEROUSLY
VACATED THE ROOMS
HOPING YOU WOULD
FIND THEM SATISFACTORY.
I DO NOT FIND THEM SO.
AND I FIND HIM
EVEN LESS SATISFACTORY.
MUST MY BITTERNESS
BE COMPOUNDED
WITH THAT
RIDICULOUS...AMBASSADOR
ABOARD YOUR SHIP?
I EXPLAINED
TO HER GLORY
THAT HER
COUNCIL OF NOBLES
AND THE
TROYIUS TRIBUNAL
JOINTLY AGREED THAT
I SHOULD INSTRUCT--
MAKE HER ACQUAINTED
WITH THE CUSTOMS AND
MANNERS OF OUR PEOPLE.
KRYTON!
REMOVE HIM!
AND TAKE THAT GARBAGE
WITH YOU!
HE DARES TO SUGGEST
THAT I ADOPT
THE SERVILE MANNERS
OF HIS PEOPLE!
YOUR GLORY DOESN'T
SEEM TO BE RESPONDING
TO INSTRUCTION.
I WILL NEVER
FORGIVE THE COUNCIL
FOR PUTTING ME
THROUGH THIS TORTURE.
WERE YOU RESPONDING
TO MY DEMAND
FOR BETTER QUARTERS?
THERE ARE NONE BETTER.
I SUGGEST YOU
MAKE DO WITH THESE.
YOU SUGGEST?!
THERE ARE
NO MORE AVAILABLE,
BUT IF THAT'S THE ONLY WAY
YOU CAN GET GRATIFICATION,
I'LL ARRANGE TO HAVE
THE WHOLE ROOM FILLED
FROM FLOOR TO CEILING
WITH BREAKABLE OBJECTS.
I WILL NOT
BE HUMILIATED!
THEN ACT IN
A CIVILIZED FASHION.
I DID NOT GIVE YOU
PERMISSION TO LEAVE!
I DIDN'T ASK FOR ANY.
OHH!
CAPTAIN, I WISH TO
CONTACT MY GOVERNMENT.
I CANNOT
FULFILL MY MISSION.
IT WOULD BE AN INSULT
TO OUR RULER
TO BRING THIS
INCORRIGIBLE MONSTER
AS A BRIDE!
AMBASSADOR!
THIS IS SUPPOSED TO BE
A PEACEFUL MISSION.
THERE CANNOT BE PEACE
BETWEEN US.
WE HAVE
DELUDED OURSELVES.
CAPTAIN,
WHEN I AM NEAR THEM,
I DO NOT WANT PEACE,
I WANT TO KILL THEM!
YOU'RE AS BAD
AS SHE IS.
IT'S NOT REQUIRED
THAT YOU LIKE EACH OTHER.
JUST...DO YOUR JOB.
THE JOB?
THE JOB IS IMPOSSIBLE.
WE CANNOT MAKE PEACE
WITH PEOPLE WE DETEST.
STOP TRYING
TO KILL EACH OTHER!
THEN WORRY ABOUT
BEING FRIENDLY.
BUT IF SHE WON'T
LISTEN TO ME--
THEN MAKE HER LISTEN,
AMBASSADOR.
USE A DIFFERENT APPROACH.
STOP BEING SO DIPLOMATIC.
SHE RESPECTS STRENGTH.
GO IN STRONG.
AT FIRST IT APPEARED
TO BE A SENSOR GHOST,
BUT I'VE RUN CHECKS
ON ALL THE INSTRUMENTATION.
ALL THE EQUIPMENT
IS FUNCTIONING PERFECTLY.
HYDROGEN CLOUD
REFLECTION?
NONE IN THIS AREA.
NOTHING THAT WOULD
ACCOUNT FOR IT.
THE GHOST APPEARS
INTERMITTENTLY.
SPECULATION.
NONE, CAPTAIN.
INSUFFICIENT DATA.
IT'S NOT AN INSTRUMENT
MALFUNCTION.
IT'S NOT A REFLECTION
FROM A NATURAL
PHENOMENON.
A SPACE SHIP?
Scotty: ENGINEERING
TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN,
I KNOW WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT SHOWING RESPECT,
BUT MUST I HAVE
THESE PERSONS
FOOL AROUND
WITH MY EQUIPMENT?
HANG ON, SCOTTY.
BE PLEASANT NO MATTER
HOW MUCH IT HURTS.
I'LL BE RIGHT DOWN.
WE'RE ONLY RUNNING
ON IMPULSE ENGINES NOW.
ORDINARILY, WE USE
THE WARP ENGINES
EXCLUSIVELY.
WELL...I SUPPOSE, UH,
LASSIE...
THAT EVEN OUR IMPULSE
ENGINES MUST SEEM FAST
COMPARED TO YOUR
NUCLEAR PROPULSION UNITS.
WE ARE INTERESTED
IN HOW THE SHIP
IS USED IN COMBAT,
NOT IN WHAT DRIVES IT.
ENGINES ARE FOR MECHANICS
AND MENIALS.
MENIALS?
WITHOUT ENGINES,
THERE'D BE NO FIGHTING OR--
Kirk: MR. SCOTT.
I WISH YOU HAD TOLD ME
THAT YOU WANTED A TOUR OF
THE ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT.
DO WE NOT HAVE
THE FREEDOM OF THIS SHIP?
WE HAVE GRANTED YOUR CREW
THE PERMISSION
NOT TO KNEEL
IN OUR PRESENCE.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT?
COURTESY. REMEMBER?
COURTESY IS NOT
FOR INFERIORS.
COURTESY IS FOR
EVERYONE AROUND HERE,
AND YOU'LL FIND
YOU WON'T BE ABLE
TO EXIST ON TROYIUS
WITHOUT IT.
MR. SCOTT,
OUR CHIEF ENGINEER,
HAS SHOWN YOU
HIS ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT.
THAT'S A COURTESY.
YOU RESPOND
BY SAYING THANK YOU.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Spock: BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
THAT SENSOR GHOST
IS MOVING CLOSER.
ON MY WAY.
LOST CONTACT NOW.
CAPTAIN, WE HAD A MOMENTARY
FIX ON THE OBJECT,
LONG ENOUGH TO ESTABLISH
IT WAS A SPACE SHIP.
WHOSE?
NO DATA YET.
Sulu: CAPTAIN.
DISTANT BEARING,
SIR.
MARK 73.5.
MAIN SCREEN.
EXTREME MAGNIFICATION.
HMM.
OUR GHOST
HAS MATERIALIZED.
A KLINGON WARSHIP.
ANY CHANGE,
MR. SPOCK?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
THE KLINGON SHIP
HAS SIMPLY MOVED
INTO CONTACT RANGE.
SHE IS PACING US,
PRECISELY MATCHING
OUR SUBLIGHT SPEED
AND ON A PARALLEL COURSE.
SECURITY TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
WHAT IS IT?
DISTURBANCE IN
THE DOHLMAN'S QUARTERS, SIR.
ON MY WAY.
CAPTAIN,
IT'S AMBASSADOR PETRI.
THEY REFUSE TO EXPLAIN
WHAT'S HAPPENING, BUT...
HER GLORY
HAS NOT SUMMONED YOU.
KRYTON,
REMOVE THAT TROYIAN PIG.
IT WAS A DEEP WOUND, JIM.
HE LOST A LOT OF BLOOD,
BUT HE'LL RECOVER.
IF I RECOVER,
IT WILL BE NO THANKS
TO YOU, CAPTAIN.
I SAID TALK WITH HER,
NOT FIGHT WITH HER.
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN BETTER
THAN TO
TALK TO HER UNARMED,
BUT YOU FORCED ME.
I HOLD YOU
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS.
WELL, I'VE HEARD OF
RELUCTANT BRIDES,
BUT THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
MAY I SPEAK
WITH YOU, SIR?
YES, CERTAINLY.
A MESSAGE JUST CAME IN
FROM STARFLEET COMMAND.
IT WAS CLASS-A SECURITY
AND SCRAMBLED.
I PUT IT THROUGH
THE DECODER.
WHAT WAS IT?
THE FEDERATION
HIGH COMMISSIONER
IS ON HIS WAY
TO TROYIUS
TO ATTEND
THE ROYAL WEDDING.
AMBASSADOR,
IF ELASIAN WOMEN
ARE THAT VICIOUS,
WHY ARE MEN
SO OVERWHELMINGLY
ATTRACTED TO THEM?
I MEAN, WHAT MAGIC
DO THEY POSSESS?
IT'S NOT MAGIC.
IT'S BIOCHEMICAL.
A MAN WHOSE FLESH
IS ONCE TOUCHED
BY THE TEARS
OF A WOMAN OF ELAS
HAS HIS HEART
ENSLAVED FOREVER.
AMBASSADOR, THERE'S
AN ADDED COMPLICATION.
THE FEDERATION
HIGH COMMISSIONER
WILL BE ATTENDING
THE WEDDING.
OH, THE FAT
WILL BE IN THE FIRE
WHEN HE LEARNS THE BRIDE
JUST TRIED TO MURDER
THE GROOM'S AMBASSADOR.
THERE WILL BE
NO WEDDING.
I WOULD NOT HAVE OUR RULER
MARRY THAT MONSTER
IF THE ENTIRE GALAXY
DEPENDED ON IT.
AND I WILL HAVE NOTHING
FURTHER TO DO WITH YOU.
I'M NOT ASKING YOU
TO HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH ME.
JUST DO YOUR JOB
WITH HER.
HOW LONG WILL IT BE
BEFORE HE'S ON HIS FEET?
IT'LL BE A FEW DAYS.
A WEEK, AT LEAST, JIM.
HERE YOU PUT ME,
CAPTAIN.
HERE I WILL STAY.
I HAVE NOTHING FURTHER
TO SAY TO YOU.
SO...
AMBASSADOR PETRI
IS GOING TO RECOVER?
THAT IS TOO BAD.
YOU HAVE DELIVERED
YOUR MESSAGE.
NOW YOU MAY GO.
NOTHING WOULD PLEASE
ME MORE, YOUR GLORY,
BUT YOUR
IMPETUOUS NATURE--
YOUR TROYIAN PIG
WAS HERE IN MY QUARTERS
WITHOUT ANY PERMISSION,
SO I STABBED HIM.
JUST TO BE TROYIAN
IS ENOUGH.
YOU ELASIANS
PRIDE YOURSELVES
ON BEING
A WARRIOR PEOPLE.
YOU MUST
UNDERSTAND DISCIPLINE,
TO BE ABLE TO GIVE
AND TAKE ORDERS.
NOW, MY ORDERS ARE
TO TAKE YOU TO TROYIUS
TO BE MARRIED
AND TO SEE TO IT
THAT YOU LEARN
TROYIAN CUSTOMS.
I DESPISE TROYIANS.
ANY CONTACT WITH THEM
MAKES ME FEEL SOILED.
IT'S BEEN MY EXPERIENCE
THAT THE PREJUDICES
PEOPLE FEEL
ABOUT EACH OTHER
DISAPPEAR WHEN THEY
GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
IT'S NOT IN MY EXPERIENCE.
WELL, WE'RE STILL FACED
WITH THE SAME PROBLEM.
PROBLEM?
YES, THE PROBLEM
OF YOUR INDOCTRINATION
TO TROYIAN CUSTOMS
AND MANNERS.
I HAVE ELIMINATED
THAT PROBLEM.
YOU HAVE ELIMINATED
THE TEACHER.
THE PROBLEM
STILL REMAINS.
OH.
AND HOW DO WE
SOLVE THE PROBLEM?
BY...
GIVING YOU
A NEW TEACHER.
[LAUGHS]
TELL ME,
WHAT CAN YOU
TEACH ME?
TABLE MANNERS,
FOR ONE THING.
THIS IS A PLATE.
IT CONTAINS FOOD.
THIS IS A KNIFE.
IT CUTS THE FOOD.
THIS IS A GLASS.
LEAVE ME!
LIKE IT OR NOT,
YOU'RE GOING TO LEARN
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
ORDERED TO LEARN!
YOU WILL RETURN ME
TO ELAS IMMEDIATELY.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
EVERYTHING I ORDER
IS POSSIBLE.
THAT'S THE FIRST PROBLEM
WE'RE GONNA WORK ON.
THEN WE'LL GET YOU
READY TO GO TO TROYIUS.
I WILL NOT
GO TO TROYIUS,
I WILL NOT BE MADE
INTO A TROYIAN,
AND I WILL NOT BE
HUMILIATED,
AND I WILL NOT BE GIVEN
TO A GREEN PIG
AS A BRIBE
TO STOP A WAR!
YOU ENJOY THE PRIVILEGES
AND PREROGATIVES
OF BEING A DOHLMAN.
THEN BE WORTHY OF THEM.
IF YOU DON'T
WANT THE OBLIGATIONS
THAT GO ALONG
WITH THE TITLE,
THEN GIVE IT UP.
NOBODY SPEAKS TO ME
THAT WAY.
THAT'S ANOTHER ONE
OF YOUR PROBLEMS.
NOBODY'S TOLD YOU
THAT YOU'RE
AN UNCIVILIZED SAVAGE,
A VICIOUS CHILD
IN A WOMAN'S BODY,
AN ARROGANT MONSTER!
THAT'S NO WAY
TO TREAT SOMEONE
WHO'S TELLING YOU
THE TRUTH.
TOMORROW'S LESSON
WILL BE ON COURTESY.
[SPITS]
LIEUTENANT, OPEN UP
THE HAILING FREQUENCY,
IDENTIFY US,
AND ASK THE KLINGON
HIS INTENTIONS.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, NO RESPONSE
FROM THE KLINGON VESSEL
ON ANY CHANNEL.
I SEE.
ALL RIGHT, LIEUTENANT.
MONITOR ALL FREQUENCIES.
PHASER CREWS STAND BY.
MAINTAIN YELLOW ALERT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
AAH!
NO ONE MAY ENTER
THE DOHLMAN'S PRESENCE.
WHERE'S KRYTON?
ON BUSINESS.
NO ONE MAY ENTER
THE DOHLMAN'S PRESENCE.
WILL YOU TELL HER GLORY
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
REQUESTS
THE HONOR OF A VISIT?
THE DOHLMAN HAS PROMISED
I'LL BE WHIPPED TO DEATH
IF I LET CAPTAIN KIRK
PASS THROUGH THAT DOOR.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
WHEN THEY WAKE UP,
TAKE THEM TO SECURITY HOLDING.
CAPTAIN, YOUR ANALYSIS
OF THE SITUATION
WAS FLAWLESS,
ANTICIPATING
THAT SHE WOULD
DENY YOU ADMITTANCE.
HOWEVER, THE LOGIC
BY WHICH YOU ARRIVED
AT YOUR CONCLUSION
ESCAPES ME.
MR. SPOCK, THE WOMEN
ON YOUR PLANET ARE LOGICAL.
THAT'S THE ONLY PLANET
IN THIS GALAXY
THAT CAN MAKE THAT CLAIM.
[DOOR OPENS]
YOU DARE TOUCH A MEMBER
OF THE ROYAL FAMILY?
ONLY IN SELF-DEFENSE.
NOW, ARE YOU GOING
TO BEHAVE OR NOT?
THE PENALTY IS DEATH
FOR WHAT YOU ARE DOING.
WE'RE NOT ON ELAS.
WE'RE ON MY STARSHIP.
I COMMAND HERE.
YOU ARE WARNED, CAPTAIN,
NEVER TO TOUCH ME AGAIN.
IF I TOUCH YOU AGAIN,
YOUR GLORY,
IT'LL BE TO ADMINISTER
AN ANCIENT EARTH CUSTOM
CALLED A SPANKING,
A FORM OF PUNISHMENT
ADMINISTERED
TO SPOILED BRATS.
YOU HAVE MY LEAVE
TO GO.
YOU FORGET, YOUR GLORY,
WE HAVEN'T STARTED
YOUR LESSON IN COURTESY.
YOU CAN TEACH ME
NOTHING, CAPTAIN.
IF I HAVE TO STAY HERE
FOR 10 LIGHT-YEARS,
I WILL NOT BE SOILED
BY ANY CONTACT WITH YOU.
VERY WELL.
I'LL SEND IN MR. SPOCK
OR DR. McCOY.
EITHER WAY, YOU'LL BE
PROPERLY PREPARED
FOR TROYIUS,
AS ORDERED BY COUNCILS,
RULERS, AND BUREAUCRATS.
CAPTAIN...
THERE IS ONE THING
YOU CAN TEACH ME.
NO, NO, YOU WERE RIGHT
THE FIRST TIME.
THERE'S NOTHING
I CAN TEACH YOU,
YOU DO NOT KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO MAKE PEOPLE LIKE ME.
I DON'T WANT EVERYBODY
TO HATE ME.
WELL, IT'S NOT...
IT'S NOT THAT
PEOPLE HATE YOU.
IT'S JUST THAT
PEOPLE DON'T LIKE
TO BE TREATED
AS THOUGH
THEY DON'T EXIST.
OHH...
IT'S, UH...
GOTTEN VERY, UH...
SOMETHING
MUST HAVE GONE WRONG
WITH THE
VENTILATION SYSTEM.
CAPTAIN...
PARDON ME,
YOUR GLORY.
THERE WILL BE
A SHORT RECESS.
CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN,
THAT ANCIENT EARTH CUSTOM
CALLED SPANKING--
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S, UM...
IT'S, UH...
WE'LL
TALK ABOUT IT LATER.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
MR. SPOCK--
I HAVE IT
ON MY SENSOR,
LIEUTENANT.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
COME IN, PLEASE.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
PLEASE ANSWER.
KIRK HERE.
OH, CAPTAIN,
I'M PICKING UP
TRANSMISSION
FROM INSIDE
THE ENTERPRISE.
IT'S ON A TIGHT BEAM
AIMED AT THE KLINGON VESSEL.
INSIDE THE ENTERPRISE?
CAN YOU PINPOINT IT?
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
I AM
TRIANGULATING NOW.
IT'S COMING FROM
THE ENGINEERING
SECTION.
SECURITY TO ENGINEERING.
INTRUDER ALERT.
SECURITY ALERT
TO ALL DECKS.
KIRK OUT.
NOBODY SAW HIM,
BUT THAT DEVIL SNEAKED
BACK IN HERE SOME WAY.
WATSON MUST HAVE
CAUGHT HIM AND WAS
KILLED FOR IT.
HE HAD THIS.
LOOKS LIKE SOME SORT
OF TRANSMITTER.
IT'S KLINGON. BONES?
CAPTAIN.
NECK SNAPPED CLEAN.
WHAT KIND OF SIGNAL
DID YOU SEND
THE KLINGON SHIP?
CAPTAIN, YOU MUST
KNOW I WILL
TELL YOU NOTHING.
OUR INTERROGATION
TECHNIQUES ARE
MORE EXCRUCIATING
THAN YOU ARE EVEN
CAPABLE OF.
YES, I'M AWARE YOU'RE
TRAINED TO RESIST
ANY FORM OF PHYSICAL
TORTURE.
KIRK TO SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE, CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK, IT WAS
KRYTON TRANSMITTING.
HE REFUSES TO TALK.
I'LL NEED YOU
FOR THE VULCAN
MIND MELD.
CAPTAIN, I'M SORRY.
BUT HE SEEMED--
WHAT WAS HE
TRYING TO COVER
THAT WAS SO IMPORTANT
HE FELT HAD TO DIE FOR IT?
SCOTTY, HE DIDN'T
COME INTO ENGINEERING
JUST TO USE
THE TRANSMITTER.
I WANT YOU TO CHECK
EVERY RELAY YOU'VE GOT.
CAPTAIN, YOU MUST
REALIZE THE TIME THAT--
DON'T WASTE THE TIME
TELLING ME ABOUT IT.
GET TO IT.
AYE.
KRYTON WAS OF
A NOBLE FAMILY.
HE LOVED ME AND WANTED
TO MARRY ME.
HE WAS FURIOUS
WHEN HE HEARD
OF THE ANNOUNCEMENT
OF THE WEDDING PLANS.
AND HE SOLD OUT
TO THE KLINGONS
BECAUSE OF JEALOUSY?
PROBABLY.
BUT WHY SPEAK
OF UNIMPORTANT MATTERS
WHEN WE CAN SPEAK
ABOUT US?
THERE'S A KLINGON
WARSHIP OUT THERE.
WHAT'S
THEIR INVOLVEMENT?
SURELY ALL OF THIS
ISN'T BECAUSE
THEY WANT TO STOP
A MARRIAGE.
WE SHOULD WELCOME
THEIR HELP.
ELAAN.
ELAAN, TWO PLANETS,
AN ENTIRE STAR SYSTEM'S
STABILITY DEPENDS ON IT.
WE HAVE A DUTY
TO FORGET WHAT HAPPENED.
COULD YOU DO THAT?
COULD YOU GIVE ME
TO ANOTHER MAN?
MY ORDERS AND YOURS
SAY THAT YOU BELONG
TO ANOTHER MAN.
WHAT HAPPENED...
WAS AN ACCIDENT.
IT WAS NO ACCIDENT.
I CHOSE YOU
AND YOU CHOSE ME.
I HAVE A PLAN.
WITH THIS SHIP,
YOU COULD COMPLETELY
OBLITERATE TROYIUS.
THEN...THERE WOULD BE
NO NEED FOR THE MARRIAGE.
AND IN GRATITUDE,
MY PEOPLE WILL GIVE YOU
THE COMPLETE RULE
OF THIS SYSTEM.
WHAT KIND OF A MIND
COULD THINK
OF SUCH A THING?
HE'S A TROYIAN.
[INTERCOM BUZZES]
[BUZZ]
Spock: CAPTAIN?
YOU CANNOT RESIST
MY LOVE, MY LOVE.
CAPTAIN?
[DOOR OPENS]
MAY WE SEE YOU
A MOMENT?
JIM.
JIM!
MAY WE PLEASE HAVE
A WORD WITH YOU?
CAPTAIN,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
DID SHE CRY, JIM?
WHAT?
DID SHE CRY?
DID HER TEARS TOUCH YOU
AT ANY TIME?
OH, WE'RE IN TROUBLE.
NOW, LISTEN, JIM,
PETRI TOLD CHRISTINE
THAT THE ELASIAN WOMEN HAVE
A SORT OF A BIOCHEMICAL
SUBSTANCE IN THEIR TEARS
THAT ACTS LIKE
A SUPER LOVE POTION.
AND ACCORDING TO HIM,
IT DOESN'T WEAR OFF.
IT IS TRUE, THEN,
CAPTAIN?
IT'S TRUE.
BONES, YOU'VE GOT TO
FIND ME AN ANTIDOTE.
I'LL TRY,
BUT I'LL NEED TESTS--
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Sulu: BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN HERE.
CAPTAIN, THE KLINGON SHIP
HAS CHANGED COURSE.
IT IS HEADING TOWARD US
AT WARP SPEED.
ON MY WAY.
BATTLE STATIONS.
[ALARM SOUNDS]
[DOOR OPENS]
PHASERS STAND BY.
PHASERS READY, SIR.
THEIR SPEED IS BETTER
THAN WARP 6, CAPTAIN.
MR. CHEKOV,
LAY IN A COURSE
TO TAKE US OUT
OF THIS STAR SYSTEM.
IF THEY WANT TO FIGHT,
LET'S GET
SOME MANEUVERING ROOM.
COURSE COMPUTED, SIR.
LAID IN, CAPTAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 2.
Scotty: CAPTAIN,
THE MATTER/ANTI-MATTER--
BELAY THAT ORDER.
WHAT IS IT, SCOTTY?
THE ANTI-MATTER PODS
ARE RIGGED TO BLOW UP
THE MOMENT WE GO
INTO WARP DRIVE.
SCOTTY, THAT BOMB HE PLANTED--
CAN YOU DISMANTLE IT?
NOT WITHOUT
BEING BLOWN HALFWAY
ACROSS THE GALAXY.
GIVE US EVERY OUNCE
OF POWER YOU CAN
FROM THE IMPULSE DRIVE.
AND FIND A SOLUTION
TO THE BOMB. KIRK OUT.
MR. SULU, STAND BY
TO MAKE YOUR
MANEUVERS SMARTLY.
SHE'LL BE SLUGGISH
ON RESPONSE.
AYE, SIR.
100,000 KILOMETERS.
90.
80.
PHASER CREWS, STAND BY
TO FIRE ON COMMAND.
60.
READY...
50.
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
SHE'S PASSED US
WITHOUT FIRING A SHOT.
I DON'T THINK
THEY MEANT
TO ATTACK US.
WE WERE
VERY FORTUNATE--
THIS TIME.
THEIR TACTICS
ARE QUITE CLEAR NOW,
MR. SPOCK.
THEY WERE TRYING
TO MAKE US
CUT IN WARP DRIVE.
THAT WAY, WE'D HAVE
BLOWN OURSELVES UP
AND SOLVED THEIR PROBLEM
FOR THEM
WITHOUT RISKING WAR
WITH THE FEDERATION.
VERY NEAT.
VERY. BUT WHY
DO THE KLINGONS
CONSIDER THE POSSESSION
OF THIS SYSTEM SO VITAL?
THAT'S A VERY GOOD
QUESTION, MR. SPOCK.
I HAVE ANOTHER
QUESTION, CAPTAIN.
IS NOT THE BRIDGE
THE WRONG PLACE
FOR THE DOHLMAN
AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
I'LL BE THE JUDGE OF--
YES, YOU'RE--
YOU'RE QUITE RIGHT.
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
I WANT YOU TO GO
TO SICK BAY.
IT'S THE
BEST-PROTECTED PART
OF THE SHIP.
I WANT TO BE BY YOUR SIDE.
YOUR PRESENCE HERE
IS INTERFERING
WITH MY EFFICIENCY,
MY ABILITY
TO PROTECT YOU.
MR. SPOCK, YOU HAVE
THE CON.
DECK FIVE.
I LOVE YOU.
I HAVE CHOSEN YOU,
AND STILL
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU DIDN'T FIGHT
THE KLINGON.
IF I CAN ACCOMPLISH
MY MISSION
BY TURNING TAIL
AND RUNNING,
I'LL GLADLY DO THAT.
AND THAT MISSION
IS TO TAKE ME TO TROYIUS.
YES.
WOULD YOU HAVE ME
WEARING MY WEDDING DRESS
FOR ANOTHER MAN
AND NEVER SEE YOU AGAIN?
YES, ELAAN.
ARE YOU HAPPY
AT THE PROSPECT?
NO.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
SCOTT TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
I'VE GOT BAD NEWS, CAPTAIN.
THE ENTIRE DILITHIUM CRYSTAL
CONVERTER ASSEMBLY IS FUSED.
NO CHANCE OF REPAIR.
IT'S COMPLETELY UNUSABLE.
NO CHANCE OF RESTORING
WARP DRIVE?
NOT WITHOUT
DILITHIUM CRYSTALS.
WE CAN'T EVEN
GENERATE ENOUGH POWER
TO FIRE OUR WEAPONS.
KIRK OUT.
ELAAN,
I HAVE TO GO BACK
TO THE BRIDGE.
PLEASE, YOU MUST GO
TO SICK BAY.
YES, MY LOVE.
TEST NUMBER 24.
COLLADIUM TRIOXIDE
IN ALGOBARIUM SOLUTION.
RESULTS ALSO NEGATIVE.
DOCTOR, THERE IS
NO ANTIDOTE
TO THE POISON
OF ELASIAN TEARS.
THE MEN OF ELAS
HAVE TRIED
DESPERATELY
FOR CENTURIES
TO DISPEL ITS POWER.
YOU'RE WASTING
YOUR TIME, DOCTOR.
IT IS MY TIME
TO WASTE, AMBASSADOR.
DOCTOR...THE CAPTAIN
ASKED ME
TO COME HERE
FOR SAFETY.
SAFETY?
WHAT IS YOUR ESTIMATE
OF OUR CHANCES
FOR SURVIVAL, DOCTOR?
THAT IS THE CAPTAIN'S
RESPONSIBILITY, AMBASSADOR.
CAPTAIN, MESSAGE
FROM THE KLINGON SHIP.
THEY ARE ORDERING US
TO STAND BY FOR BOARDING
OR BE DESTROYED.
THEY DEMAND
AN IMMEDIATE REPLY.
THEY'RE TRYING
TO FORCE A FIGHT.
SCOTTY, WHAT'S
OUR ENERGY STATUS?
93% OF IMPULSE POWER, SIR.
WE CAN
STILL MANEUVER.
MANEUVER? AYE.
WE CAN WALLOW LIKE
A GARBAGE SCOW
AGAINST A WARP-DRIVEN
STARSHIP.
OUR SHIELDS WILL HOLD
FOR A FEW PASSES,
BUT WITHOUT THE MATTER/
ANTI-MATTER REACTOR,
WE'VE NO CHANCE.
CAPTAIN, CAN YOU NOT
CALL STARFLEET
ON THIS EMERGENCY?
AND LET THE KLINGONS
KNOW THEY SUCCEEDED
IN WIPING OUT
OUR WARP ENGINES?
HELP COULD NOT
POSSIBLY ARRIVE
BEFORE THE ENTERPRISE
WOULD BE DESTROYED.
NOW THAT WE
ARE ALL ABOUT TO DIE,
I ASK YOU ONCE AGAIN
TO ACCEPT THIS NECKLACE
AND TO WEAR IT
AS A TOKEN OF RESPECT
FOR THE DESPERATE WISHES
OF YOUR PEOPLE AND MINE
FOR PEACE.
THAT'S ALL YOU MEN
OF OTHER WORLDS
CAN SPEAK OF,
DUTY AND
RESPONSIBILITY.
WE'LL STALL FOR TIME.
PROCEED ON COURSE
AND HOPE THE KLINGONS
CAN BE BLUFFED,
OR THAT THEY'RE
NOT PREPARED
FOR A GENERAL WAR.
OPEN A HAILING FREQUENCY.
FREQUENCY OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE
ON FEDERATION BUSINESS.
OUR MISSION IS PEACEFUL,
BUT WE'RE NOT PREPARED
TO ACCEPT ANY INTERFERENCE.
ENTERPRISE,
PREPARE TO BE BOARDED
OR DESTROYED.
I'D SAY OUR STRATEGY
WASN'T TOTALLY EFFECTIVE.
CAPTAIN, THE KLINGON
SHIP IS CLOSING
ON AN INTERCEPT COURSE.
500,000 KILOMETERS.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS UP.
SCOTTY, CAN YOU
GIVE ME PARTIAL POWER
ON THE PHASER BANKS?
NO, SIR,
NOT A CHANCE.
300,000 KILOMETERS.
I TOLD YOU
TO STAY IN SICK BAY.
I WANT TO DIE WITH YOU.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO DIE.
NOW GET OFF THE BRIDGE.
100,000 KILOMETERS.
[EXPLOSION]
HE'S PASSED US.
ALL SHIELDS HELD.
MR. SULU, BRING HER
TO 143 MARK 2.
KEEP OUR FORWARD
SHIELDS TO HIM.
HERE HE COMES AGAIN, SIR.
STAY WITH THE CONTROLS.
KEEP OUR FORWARD
SHIELDS TO HIM.
BETTER THAN WARP 7.
HARD OVER, SULU.
BRING HER AROUND.
HE'S GOING
FOR OUR FLANK.
SULU!
SORRY, CAPTAIN.
SHE WON'T RESPOND
FAST ENOUGH ON IMPULSE.
HE'S PASSED US AGAIN.
DAMAGE TO NUMBER FOUR
SHIELD.
HOW BAD?
IT WILL NOT WITHSTAND
ANOTHER FULL CHARGE, CAPTAIN.
I'M GETTING SOME VERY
PECULIAR ENERGY READINGS.
HE'S PARALLELING US
AGAIN.
HE SEEMS TO HAVE
BROKEN OFF THE ATTACK.
WHAT SORT OF READINGS,
MR. SPOCK?
SHE IS THE SOURCE.
ELAAN?
THE NECKLACE.
WHAT KIND OF JEWELS
ARE IN THIS?
THEY CALL THEM
RADANS.
THE NECKLACE
IS SUPPOSED TO
BRING YOU LUCK.
IT IS
OF LITTLE VALUE.
THEY ARE
COMMON STONES.
THESE ARE COMMON STONES?
SEE, CAPTAIN?
HERE AND HERE.
COMMON STONES?
NOW I SEE WHY
THE KLINGONS ARE INTERESTED
IN THIS SYSTEM.
MAY I HAVE THIS?
IF I CAN BE OF
ANY HELP, OF COURSE.
YOU MAY HAVE
JUST SAVED OUR LIVES.
MR. SPOCK, DO YOU THINK
SCOTTY COULD MAKE USE
OF DILITHIUM CRYSTALS?
NO DOUBT, CAPTAIN.
HE'S COMING IN
AGAIN, SIR.
MR. SULU,
PREPARE ON MY ORDER
TO TURN QUICKLY
TO PORT.
TRY AND PROTECT
THE NUMBER FOUR SHIELD.
AYE, SIR.
NOW, SULU.
HARD TO PORT!
SHIELDS HOLDING,
BUT WEAKENED, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
MESSAGE COMING IN.
ENTERPRISE,
OUR READINGS CONFIRM
YOUR POWER
EXTREMELY LOW,
YOUR SHIELDS BUCKLING.
THIS IS YOUR LAST CHANCE
TO SURRENDER.
CAPTAIN,
NUMBER FOUR SHIELD
JUST COLLAPSED.
IMPULSE POWER
DOWN TO 31%.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN A HAILING FREQUENCY.
CHANNEL OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK
OF THE UNITED SPACE SHIP
ENTERPRISE.
MAY I REQUEST YOUR TERMS
FOR SURRENDER?
NO TERMS.
SURRENDER MUST BE
UNCONDITIONAL
AND IMMEDIATE.
SCOTTY, YOUR ESTIMATE.
WE'RE FITTING IT
NOW, SIR,
BUT WE'LL HAVE TO RUN
A FEW TESTS TO MAKE SURE.
TEST IT IN COMBAT.
CAPTAIN, THESE ARE
CRUDE CRYSTALS.
THERE IS NO WAY TO JUDGE
WHAT THE UNUSUAL
SHAPES WILL DO
TO THE ENERGY FLOW.
WHY, THAT COULD
BLOW US UP JUST
AS EFFECTIVELY AS--
LET ME KNOW
WHEN IT'S IN PLACE.
OPEN A HAILING FREQUENCY.
HAILING FREQUENCY
OPEN, SIR.
THIS IS THE ENTERPRISE.
WILL YOU GUARANTEE
THE SAFETY
OF OUR PASSENGER,
THE DOHLMAN FROM ELAS?
NO CONDITIONS.
SURRENDER
IMMEDIATELY.
CAPTAIN,
HE'S STARTING HIS RUN.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
SCOTT TO CAPTAIN.
IT'S IN PLACE, SIR,
BUT I CAN'T ANSWER
FOR WHAT HAPPENS.
YOU AND SPOCK GET UP HERE.
SULU, PREPARE
FOR WARP MANEUVERS.
AYE, SIR.
CHEKOV, ARM PHOTON
TORPEDOES.
PHOTON TORPEDOES
READY.
WARP POWER
TO THE SHIELDS,
CAPTAIN?
NEGATIVE.
HIS SENSORS WILL PICK UP
OUR POWER INCREASE.
THE MORE HELPLESS
HE THINKS WE ARE,
THE CLOSER HE'LL COME.
AS HE PASSES,
I WANT TO CUT IN WARP DRIVE.
WE'LL PIVOT AT WARP 2
AND BRING ALL TUBES TO BEAR.
AYE, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV, GIVE HIM
A FULL SPREAD
OF PHOTON TORPEDOES.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
100,000 KILOMETERS.
SCOTTY, STAND BY
TO CUT IN WARP DRIVE.
FLUCTUATION.
IT'S THE SHAPE
OF THE CRYSTALS.
I WAS AFRAID OF THAT.
75.
70.
60.
50.
FIRE
AT MINIMUM RANGE.
40.
SHE WON'T STEADY DOWN.
30.
WARP IN, SCOTTY.
FULL POWER TO SHIELDS.
WARP FACTOR 2.
LAY US A COURSE
148 MARK 3.
CHEKOV...
PHOTON TORPEDOES--
FIRE!
AYE, SIR.
DIRECT HIT AMIDSHIPS
BY PHOTON TORPEDO.
DAMAGE TO KLINGON
NUMBER THREE SHIELD.
NUMBER FOUR SHIELD
OBLITERATED.
LOSS OF MANEUVER POWER.
HE'S BADLY DAMAGED,
CAPTAIN.
CONTINUING AWAY
AT REDUCED SPEED.
SECURE FROM
GENERAL QUARTERS.
WELL DONE, MR. SULU.
SCOTTY.
BUT I DON'T
UNDERSTAND YOU.
YOU MEAN YOU WON'T PURSUE
AND FINISH HIM OFF?
NO.
MR. SULU, RESUME COURSE
FOR TROYIUS.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
YOU WILL NOT BEAM DOWN
FOR THE CEREMONY?
NO.
I WANT YOU
TO HAVE THIS
AS A PERSONAL
MEMENTO.
I HAVE LEARNED
THAT ON TROYIUS,
THEY DO NOT WEAR
SUCH THINGS.
REMEMBER ME.
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
NOR HAVE I.
I HAVE ONLY
RESPONSIBILITIES...
AND OBLIGATIONS.
GOOD-BYE.
ENERGIZE.
IT'S STABILIZED NOW.
SPOCK, I'VE ISOLATED
THE BIOCHEMICAL SUBSTANCE
OF THE ELASIAN TEARS.
IT'S A KIND OF INFECTION,
AND I THINK I FOUND
AN ANTIDOTE FOR IT.
YOU'RE TOO LATE, DOCTOR.
THE CAPTAIN HAS FOUND
HIS OWN ANTIDOTE.
ARE YOU OUT
OF YOUR VULCAN MIND?
DO YOU KNOW HOW LONG
I'VE WORKED ON THAT--
THE ANTIDOTE
TO A WOMAN OF ELAS,
DOCTOR, IS A STARSHIP.
THE ENTERPRISE
INFECTED THE CAPTAIN
LONG BEFORE
THE DOHLMAN DID.
MR. SULU, PREPARE
TO TAKE US OUT OF ORBIT.
WELL, I DOUBT SERIOUSLY
IF THERE'S
ANY KIND OF AN ANTIDOTE
FOR THE ENTERPRISE.
IN THIS PARTICULAR
INSTANCE, DOCTOR,
I AGREE WITH YOU.
AHEAD WARP FACTOR 2.