Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5718.3.
THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS ORBITING ELBA II,
A PLANET WITH
A POISONOUS ATMOSPHERE
WHERE THE FEDERATION
MAINTAINS AN ASYLUM
FOR THE FEW REMAINING
INCORRIGIBLE, CRIMINALLY INSANE
OF THE GALAXY.
WE ARE BRINGING A REVOLUTIONARY
NEW MEDICINE TO THEM,
A MEDICINE WITH WHICH
THE FEDERATION HOPES
TO ELIMINATE MENTAL ILLNESS
FOR ALL TIME.
I AM TRANSPORTING DOWN
WITH MR. SPOCK,
AND WE'RE DELIVERING
THE MEDICINE
TO DR. DONALD CORY,
THE GOVERNOR OF THE COLONY.
DONALD.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
GOVERNOR.
GENTLEMEN,
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT A TREAT
THIS IS FOR ME.
IT'S BEEN TOO LONG
SINCE I'VE HAD
COMPANY, JIM.
THE FORCE FIELD'S
BACK IN PLACE NOW.
THAT MEANS YOU TWO
ARE TRAPPED HERE,
AND I'M NOT ACCEPTING
ANY EXCUSES
FOR YOUR NOT DINING
WITH ME.
Kirk:
WE'D BE DELIGHTED.
GOVERNOR,
YOU INDICATED ONE
ADDITIONAL INMATE
SINCE
OUR LAST VISIT,
MAKING
A TOTAL OF 15.
IS THAT CORRECT?
IT IS. THE
REHABILITATION PROGRAM
ISN'T PROGRESSING
TOO WELL,
AND I HAVE MY DOUBTS
ABOUT THE EFFECTIVENESS
OF THIS MEDICINE, TOO.
WHY, DONALD, ARE YOU
BECOMING A PESSIMIST?
[CHUCKLING]
I'M AFRAID I HAVE.
A TOTAL OF
15 INCURABLY INSANE
OUT OF BILLIONS
IS NOT
WHAT I WOULD CALL
AN EXCESSIVE FIGURE.
WHO IS
THE NEW INMATE?
GARTH.
GARTH OF IZAR, A FORMER
STARSHIP FLEET CAPTAIN.
Kirk: WHEN I WAS A CADET
AT THE ACADEMY,
HIS EXPLOITS
WERE REQUIRED READING.
HE WAS ONE
OF MY HEROES.
I'D LIKE
TO SEE HIM, DONALD.
OF COURSE.
Woman: CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE MAKING
A MISTAKE.
CAPTAIN KIRK
IS PRESSED FOR TIME
AT THE MOMENT, MARTA.
THERE'S NOTHING
THE MATTER WITH ME.
CAN'T YOU SEE
JUST BY LOOKING AT ME?
CAN'T YOU TELL
JUST BY LISTENING?
SHE SOUNDS
RATIONAL ENOUGH,
CAPTAIN.
I AM RATIONAL.
WELL, WHAT IS IT
YOU WANT TO TELL ME?
I CAN'T TELL YOU
IN FRONT OF HIM.
YOU'RE AFRAID
TO TALK IN FRONT
OF GOVERNOR CORY?
HE ISN'T REALLY
GOVERNOR CORY AT ALL.
THAT'S JUST IT.
SHE'S BEEN SAYING
THAT FOR DAYS NOW.
OUR MEDICAL STAFF
CAN'T FIGURE OUT WHY.
HERE'S GARTH. HE'S BEEN
UNUSUALLY DISTURBED,
AND WE'VE HAD TO IMPOSE
ADDITIONAL RESTRAINT.
CORY?
YES, JIM. I'M CORY.
[LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
IT'S TRUE.
HE TRICKED YOU.
[LAUGHING]
YOU SAID YOU WANTED
TO SEE ME, CAPTAIN.
WELL, HERE I AM.
HA HA HA!
SPACE:
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
YOUR VULCAN FRIEND
IS STILL ALIVE, CAPTAIN.
MY PHASER WAS SET
TO STUN, NOT TO KILL.
HE'LL BE QUITE
COMFORTABLE...
ALMOST AS COMFORTABLE
AS YOU AND OUR
ESTEEMED GOVERNOR.
GARTH, DO YOU
HAVE TO MAKE HIM
SUFFER LIKE THAT?
YOU WILL ADDRESS ME
BY MY PROPER TITLE, KIRK.
I'M SORRY.
I SHOULD HAVE SAID,
"CAPTAIN GARTH."
I AM LORD GARTH,
FORMERLY OF IZAR,
AND I LEAD THE FUTURE
MASTERS OF THE UNIVERSE.
I'M SORRY, LORD GARTH.
YOU EARTH PEOPLE
ARE A STIFF-NECKED
LOT, AREN'T YOU?
RELEASE HIM.
I'M AFRAID THAT
SUBJUGATING YOU
WON'T BE ENOUGH.
YOU MUST BE CONFINED,
AND ALL THE PEOPLE
OF THE GALAXY
WHO WILL NOT BOW
TO MY WILL
MUST BE CONFINED
OR DESTROYED.
CAPTAIN GARTH,
LISTEN TO ME.
HO HO!
OUR BELOVED GOVERNOR
HAS DECIDED TO ADDRESS US,
AND WE HAVE NOT GIVEN HIM
OUR PERMISSION TO SPEAK.
ARE YOU SO AFRAID
OF HIM THAT YOU MUST
KEEP HIM PINNED?
I'M AFRAID OF NO ONE!
YOU'RE ALL POWERLESS
AGAINST ME.
THANK YOU.
NOW, WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE WITH THE MEDICINE?
THE MEDICINE?
YOU MEAN, THE POISON.
I DESTROYED IT
AT THE PORT.
DESTROYED IT?!
IT WAS YOUR ONLY HOPE.
SILENCE!
THE CHATTER OF INFERIOR
WEAKLINGS WEARIES ME,
AND IT'S TIME I TOOK
COMMAND OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
YOU'LL HELP ME, OF COURSE.
[SARCASTICALLY]
OF COURSE.
MY CREW MUTINIED.
THE FIRST USE I WILL MAKE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS TO HUNT THEM DOWN
AND PUNISH THEM FOR THAT.
THE CREW OF
THE "ENTERPRISE"
WILL ALSO MUTINY.
HEH HEH. BUT THEY WON'T!
YOU SEE, CAPTAIN,
THERE'S A HELPFUL
TECHNIQUE I'VE MASTERED.
HA HA HA!
GOOD-BYE, DARLING.
I'LL MISS YOU.
HA HA HA!
GOVERNOR CORY,
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
ALL RIGHT.
THERE IS NO HELP
FOR ANY OF US
IF THAT MADMAN
IS IN COMMAND
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
HE BOASTS
THAT HE'S CREATED
THE MOST
POWERFUL EXPLOSIVE
IN THE UNIVERSE,
AND I BELIEVE HIM.
HOW DOES HE MANAGE
TO CHANGE FORM AT WILL?
THE PEOPLE OF ANTOS
TAUGHT HIM
THE TECHNIQUES
OF CELLULAR
METAMORPHOSIS
TO RESTORE
THE DESTROYED PARTS
OF HIS BODY.
BY HIMSELF,
HE LATER LEARNED
TO USE THE TECHNIQUE
TO RE-CREATE HIMSELF
INTO ANY FORM
HE WISHED.
THE FIRST TIME
WE KNEW ABOUT IT
WAS WHEN A GUARD,
SEEING WHAT HE
THOUGHT WAS ME
IN GARTH'S CELL,
RELEASED HIM.
HE WAS SUCH A GENIUS.
WHAT A WASTE.
FORCE FIELD'S OFF.
GOOD. REMAIN HERE,
OUT OF SIGHT,
UNTIL I GIVE YOU
THE ORDER TO JOIN ME.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
BEAM ME ABOARD.
AYE, SIR. QUEEN
TO QUEEN'S LEVEL 3.
I SAID,
"BEAM ME ABOARD."
I SAID, "QUEEN
TO QUEEN'S LEVEL 3."
WE HAVE NO TIME
FOR CHESS PROBLEMS.
BEAM ME ABOARD.
I'M FOLLOWING
YOUR ORDERS, CAPTAIN.
QUEEN
TO QUEEN'S LEVEL 3.
JUST TESTING.
BE IN TOUCH
WITH YOU LATER.
NO!
[MOANING]
AAH!
I GAVE HIM THE SIGN.
WHY DIDN'T HE GIVE ME
THE COUNTERSIGN?
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
USING
THE CHESS PROBLEM
WAS THE CAPTAIN'S
OWN SUGGESTION.
HE COULDN'T HAVE
FORGOTTEN IT,
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
HE WAS TESTING ME.
LIEUTENANT,
REESTABLISH
COMMUNICATION.
AYE, SIR.
THERE'S NO RESPONSE,
MR. SCOTT.
SEND AN ARMED
DETAIL
TO THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM IMMEDIATELY.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
MR. SULU, WHAT DO
YOUR SENSORS SHOW?
WE CAN'T BEAM
ANYBODY DOWN, SIR.
THE FORCE FIELD
ON THE PLANET
IS IN FULL
OPERATION, AND ALL
FORMS OF TRANSPORT
INTO THE ASYLUM DOME
ARE BLOCKED OFF.
WELL, WE COULD
BLAST OUR WAY
THROUGH THE FIELD,
BUT ONLY AT THE RISK
OF DESTROYING
THE CAPTAIN, MR. SPOCK,
AND ANY OTHER LIVING
THING ON ELBA II.
HOW CAN WE BE
POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO WIPE OUT A PLANET
AND STILL BE
SO HELPLESS?
WE ARE GOING TO TAKE
THE "ENTERPRISE."
DO YOU HEAR ME?
WE ARE GOING TO
TAKE HER,
IF I HAVE TO
SHATTER EVERY BONE
IN CAPTAIN KIRK'S BODY.
CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN KIRK!
WELL, I HOPE YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN TOO UNCOMFORTABLE,
CAPTAIN.
I THANK YOU
FOR YOUR CONCERN.
ALL IN ALL,
IT'S BEEN RATHER RESTFUL.
GOOD. STILL, I'M AFRAID
I'VE BEEN QUITE REMISS
IN MY DUTIES
AS YOUR HOST.
BUT I DID INVITE YOU
DOWN TO DINNER,
AS YOU MAY RECALL.
I'VE FORGOTTEN.
BUT I HAVEN'T.
YOU AND MR. SPOCK
ARE TO BE MY GUESTS.
WHERE IS MR. SPOCK?
RIGHT HERE.
MARTA!
WHY CAN'T I
BLOW OFF JUST ONE
OF HIS EARS?
STOP THAT, MARTA.
MR. SPOCK WILL
THINK WE'RE LACKING
IN HOSPITALITY.
WON'T YOU JOIN US,
CAPTAIN?
HOW ARE YOU,
MR. SPOCK?
VERY WELL, INDEED.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
ISN'T GOVERNOR CORY
JOINING US?
NO. THE GOVERNOR
DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
ON THE GUEST LIST.
OH? AN OVERSIGHT?
AN INTENTIONAL ONE.
THE GOVERNOR'S
FASTING.
IN THAT CASE,
WE MUST DECLINE
WITH THANKS.
UH, CAPTAIN...
DON'T BE A FOOL, JIM.
GO ALONG WITH HIM.
GOOD ADVICE,
GOVERNOR.
WELL, CAPTAIN?
YOU'LL FIND WE SET
A HANDSOME TABLE,
AND THE
ENTERTAINMENT
IS MOST ENJOYABLE.
YOU'RE VERY
PERSUASIVE.
YES, I AM.
I CERTAINLY AM.
HYAH!
KEEP YOUR HANDS
OFF KIRK!
YOU TREACHEROUS
THING.
HA HA HA!
YOU'RE JEALOUS.
I AM ABOVE
THAT SORT OF THING.
THE CAPTAIN IS ANNOYED
BY YOUR ATTENTIONS,
THAT'S ALL.
AM I ANNOYING YOU,
DEAREST?
WELL, NOT REALLY.
HA HA! HE FINDS ME
FASCINATING,
AND YOU'RE
BOTHERED BY IT.
ADMIT IT.
I MAY HAVE YOU
BEATEN TO DEATH.
NO, YOU WON'T,
BECAUSE I AM
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
WOMAN ON THIS PLANET.
YOU'RE THE ONLY WOMAN
ON THIS PLANET,
YOU STUPID COW.
WELL, I'M THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
IN THIS GALAXY.
YOU'RE REPULSIVE.
Marta: I'M BEAUTIFUL!
AND I'M
INTELLIGENT, TOO.
I WRITE POETRY,
AND I PAINT
MARVELOUS PICTURES,
AND I AM
A WONDERFUL DANCER.
LIES. ALL LIES!
YOU ARE THE GREATEST LIAR
I HAVE EVER MET!
LET ME HEAR ONE POEM
YOU'VE WRITTEN.
IF YOU LIKE.
Spock:
CAPTAIN, IF YOU COULD
CREATE A DIVERSION,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO FIND
THE CONTROL ROOM
AND OPEN
THE FORCE FIELD.
ALL WE NEED
IS A FEW SECONDS,
BECAUSE SCOTTY HAS ALERTED
THE SECURITY DETAIL.
GENTLEMEN, COURTESY
FOR THE PERFORMER.
SHALL I COMPARE THEE
TO A SUMMER'S DAY?
THOU ART MORE LOVELY
AND MORE TEMPERATE.
ROUGH WINDS DO SHAKE
THE DARLING BUDS OF MAY,
AND SUMMER'S LEASE
HATH ALL--
YOU WROTE THAT?!
YESTERDAY,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
IT WAS WRITTEN
BY AN EARTHMAN
NAMED SHAKESPEARE
A LONG TIME AGO.
WHICH DOES NOT
ALTER THE FACT
THAT I WROTE IT
AGAIN YESTERDAY.
I THINK IT'S ONE
OF MY BEST POEMS,
DON'T YOU?
I MAY KILL YOU
WITH MY BARE HANDS!
ACTUALLY, CAPTAIN,
SHE IS A SUPERB DANCER.
MARTA, MY DEAR,
WON'T YOU DANCE
FOR OUR GUESTS?
THAT WAS NOT
A REQUEST.
[GONG SOUNDS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
MARVELOUS,
ISN'T SHE, CAPTAIN?
YES. UM...INCREDIBLE.
WHAT IS YOUR REACTION,
MR. SPOCK?
WELL, I FIND
IT, UM...
MILDLY INTERESTING
AND SOMEWHAT NOSTALGIC,
IF I UNDERSTAND
THE USE OF THAT WORD.
NOSTALGIC?
YES, IT IS SOMEWHAT
REMINISCENT
OF THE DANCES THAT
VULCAN CHILDREN DO
IN NURSERY SCHOOL.
OF COURSE, THE CHILDREN
ARE NOT SO...
WELL-COORDINATED.
[APPLAUSE]
SHE'S YOURS
IF YOU WISH, CAPTAIN.
OH, UH...
THANK YOU.
THAT'S, UM...
VERY MAGNANIMOUS
OF YOU.
WELL, YOU'LL FIND
THAT I AM MAGNANIMOUS...
TO MY FRIENDS
AND MERCILESS
TO MINE ENEMIES.
AND I WANT YOU,
BOTH OF YOU,
TO BE MY FRIENDS.
ON WHAT, PRECISELY,
IS OUR FRIENDSHIP
TO BE BASED?
WELL, UPON THE FIRMEST
OF FOUNDATIONS, MR. SPOCK:
ENLIGHTENED
SELF-INTEREST.
YOU, CAPTAIN,
ARE SECOND ONLY TO ME
AS THE FINEST MILITARY
COMMANDER IN THE GALAXY.
Kirk: THAT'S
VERY FLATTERING.
I...AM PRIMARILY
AN EXPLORER NOW,
CAPTAIN GARTH.
AND SO HAVE I BEEN.
I HAVE CHARTED
MORE NEW WORLDS
THAN ANY MAN
IN HISTORY.
AND TRIED TO DESTROY
ANTOS IV.
WHY?
WELL, I COULD SAY
BECAUSE THEY WERE
ACTIVELY HOSTILE
TO THE FEDERATION.
YES, YOU COULD SAY,
BUT THAT WOULD
BE UNTRUE.
AGREED.
ACTUALLY, THEY WERE
QUITE HARMLESS,
AND THEY MADE ME WHOLE
WHEN I WAS MAIMED
AND DYING.
AND IN MY GRATITUDE,
I OFFERED THEM
THE GALAXY.
THEY REJECTED ME,
AND I CONDEMNED
THEM TO DEATH.
HOW COULD YOU,
A STARSHIP FLEET
CAPTAIN,
BELIEVE THAT
A FEDERATION CREW
WOULD BLINDLY OBEY
YOUR ORDER
TO DESTROY THE ENTIRE
ANTOS RACE,
A PEOPLE FAMOUS
FOR THEIR BENEVOLENCE
AND PEACEFUL PURSUITS?
THAT WAS MY ONLY
MISCALCULATION.
I HAD CHANGED.
I HAD RISEN ABOVE
THIS DECADENT WEAKNESS,
WHICH STILL HAS YOU
IN ITS COMMAND,
BY THE WAY, CAPTAIN.
MY CREW HAD NOT.
I COULDN'T SWAY THEM.
BUT MY NEW CREW,
YOU MET IN THIS ROOM,
WILL OBEY MY ORDERS
WITHOUT QUESTION.
GENTLEMEN,
YOU HAVE EYES,
BUT YOU CANNOT SEE.
GALAXIES SURROUND US,
LIMITLESS VISTAS,
AND YET THE FEDERATION
WOULD HAVE US
DRUM AWAY LIKE SOME ANTS
ON SOME...SOMEWHAT LARGER
THAN USUAL ANTHILL.
BUT I AM NOT AN INSECT.
I AM MASTER
OF THE UNIVERSE,
AND I MUST CLAIM
MY DOMAIN.
I AGREE THERE WAS A TIME
WHEN WAR WAS NECESSARY,
AND YOU WERE
OUR GREATEST WARRIOR.
I STUDIED
YOUR VICTORY AT AXENAR
WHEN I WAS A CADET.
IN FACT, IT'S STILL
REQUIRED READING
AT THE ACADEMY.
AS WELL IT SHOULD BE.
VERY WELL. BUT MY FIRST
VISIT TO AXENAR
WAS AS A NEW-FLEDGED CADET
ON A PEACE MISSION.
PEACE MISSION!
POLITICIANS AND WEAKLINGS!
THEY WERE HUMANITARIANS
AND STATESMEN,
AND THEY HAD A DREAM,
A DREAM THAT BECAME
A REALITY
AND SPREAD THROUGHOUT
THE STARS,
A DREAM THAT MADE
MR. SPOCK AND ME BROTHERS.
MR. SPOCK!
YOU CONSIDER CAPTAIN KIRK
AND YOURSELF BROTHERS?
CAPTAIN KIRK SPEAKS
SOMEWHAT FIGURATIVELY
AND WITH UNDUE EMOTION.
HOWEVER, WHAT HE SAYS
IS LOGICAL,
AND I DO, IN FACT,
AGREE WITH IT.
BLIND! TRULY BLIND.
CAPTAIN KIRK IS
YOUR COMMANDING OFFICER!
YOU ARE HIS SUBORDINATE,
AND THAT IS ALL.
YET, MR. SPOCK, YOU
ARE A WORTHY COMMANDER
IN YOUR OWN RIGHT,
AND IN MY FLEET,
YOU WILL SURELY HAVE
A STARSHIP TO COMMAND.
PLEASE FORGIVE ME,
BUT EXACTLY WHERE
IS YOUR FLEET?
OUT THERE
WAITING FOR ME.
THEY WILL FLOCK
TO MY CAUSE,
AND FOR GOOD REASON--
LIMITLESS POWER,
LIMITLESS WILL,
AND SOLAR SYSTEMS
RULED BY THE ELITE.
WE, GENTLEMEN,
ARE THAT ELITE,
AND WE MUST TAKE
WHAT IS RIGHTFULLY OURS
FROM THE DECADENT
WEAKLINGS THAT NOW HOLD IT.
CAPTAIN GARTH...
LORD GARTH.
AS YOU WISH.
AT ANY RATE,
YOU MUST BE AWARE
OF THE FACT
THAT YOU
ARE ATTEMPTING
TO RE-CREATE
THE DISASTER
WHICH RESULTED
IN YOUR BECOMING
AN INMATE
IN THIS PLACE.
I WAS BETRAYED
AND TREATED BARBARICALLY.
ON THE CONTRARY.
YOU WERE TREATED
WITH JUSTICE
AND WITH COMPASSION,
WHICH YOU
FAILED TO SHOW
TOWARDS ANY
OF YOUR INTENDED
VICTIMS.
LOGICALLY,
THEREFORE, ONE
MUST ASSUME--
REMOVE THIS ANIMAL!
WON'T YOU TRY
SOME OF THIS WINE,
CAPTAIN?
IT HAS A ROBUST,
FULL-BODIED FLAVOR,
WHICH I AM SURE
YOU'LL FIND DIVERTING.
NO, THANK YOU.
I PREFER TO JOIN
MR. SPOCK.
AND I PREFER
THAT YOU REMAIN HERE.
MARTA, MY DEAR?
WE FOUND YOUR LITTLE
DIVERTISSEMENT ENCHANTING,
DIDN'T WE, CAPTAIN?
BUT THERE'S MUCH,
MUCH MORE TO COME.
THE ENTERTAINMENT
HAS MERELY BEGUN.
BY THE WAY,
I ASSUME YOU PLAY CHESS.
OCCASIONALLY.
SO DO I. HOW WOULD
YOU RESPOND TO QUEEN
TO QUEEN'S LEVEL 3?
I'M SURE
YOU'RE AWARE
THAT THERE ARE
AN INFINITE NUMBER
OF COUNTERMOVES.
I'M INTERESTED
IN ONLY ONE.
I CAN'T,
FOR THE LIFE OF ME,
IMAGINE WHICH ONE.
"FOR THE LIFE
OF ME" IS A PHRASE
WELL-CHOSEN, CAPTAIN.
IT COULD LITERALLY
COME TO THAT.
DEAD, I AM
OF NO USE TO YOU.
BUT I CAN MAKE YOU
LONG FOR DEATH,
BEG FOR DEATH.
IN THE MIDNIGHT
OF NOVEMBER,
WHEN THE DEAD MAN'S
FAIR IS NIGH,
AND THE DANGER IN THE VALLEY
AND THE ANGER IN THE SKY.
I WROTE THAT
THIS MORNING.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
YES, I THINK
IT'S VERY GOOD.
TELL HIM WHAT
HE WANTS TO KNOW,
AND WE'LL GO AWAY
TOGETHER.
I CAN'T.
OH, BUT YOU MUST,
I BEG OF YOU!
OH, DON'T BEG,
MARTA.
IT'S...DEGRADING.
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3, CAPTAIN.
YOU'LL TALK FREELY...
AND QUITE SOON.
WHAT YOU SEE
BEFORE YOU, CAPTAIN,
IS MY LATEST INVENTION.
QUITE ORDINARY
IN APPEARANCE.
ALMOST PRIMITIVE,
WOULDN'T YOU SAY?
YES, I RECOGNIZE IT.
IT'S USED FOR
REHABILITATION PURPOSES.
IT HELPED MANY MEN
BACK TO HEALTH.
APPEARANCES
CAN BE DECEIVING.
ONCE IT WAS A PART
OF THE REHABILITATION
PROCESS,
AND AS SUCH,
QUITE PAINLESS,
AND I MIGHT ADD,
USELESS, TOO.
IT MADE MEN DOCILE
AND OF NO USE TO ME.
I'VE ADDED
CERTAIN REFINEMENTS
TO THE USE
OF ULTRASONIC WAVES.
THE CHAIR
IS NO LONGER PAINLESS.
PUT THE GOVERNOR IN IT.
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S LEVEL 3,
CAPTAIN KIRK?
IT IS, IN FACT,
EXQUISITELY PAINFUL,
AS YOU WILL NOW SEE.
[LOW WAVERING HUM]
INTERESTING, ISN'T IT?
THE PAIN IS REAL
AND CAN BE PROLONGED
INDEFINITELY
BECAUSE THERE IS
NO ACTUAL DESTRUCTION
OF TISSUE.
STOP IT!
[GASPING]
OF COURSE,
CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE
BUT TO ASK.
NOW, AS
YOU CAN SEE,
HE HAS NOT BEEN HARMED
PHYSICALLY,
YET THE MEMORY
OF THE EXQUISITE
TORMENT REMAINS.
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3, CAPTAIN.
NO.
TOO BAD.
REMOVE OUR
DISTINGUISHED GOVERNOR
AND PUT CAPTAIN KIRK
IN THE CHAIR.
NO, YOU MUSTN'T
DO THAT!
YOU REALLY ARE
BECOMING
OFFENSIVE TO ME,
MY DEAR.
DON'T MAKE IT
NECESSARY FOR ME
TO PUT YOU IN IT.
[LOW WAVERING HUM]
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3, CAPTAIN KIRK.
[LOW WAVERING HUM]
PLEASE, STOP IT!
YOU WANT HIM,
DON'T YOU?
YES.
BADLY ENOUGH
TO JOIN HIM?
LISTEN TO ME,
MY LORD GARTH.
I CAN GET HIM
TO TELL ME
WHAT YOU WANT TO KNOW.
MIGHT BE INTERESTING
TO HAVE YOU TRY.
[HUMMING STOPS]
NO BREAKTHROUGH?
NO, MR. SCOTT.
STILL NO RESPONSE
FROM THE PLANET.
SENSOR READINGS?
THE FORCE FIELD
IS WEAKEST
ON THE FAR SIDE
OF THE PLANET.
WE CAN SEND DOWN
A SHUTTLECRAFT
CARRYING A TEAM
IN ENVIRONMENTAL
SUITS.
IT WON'T WORK, SCOTTY.
THEY'D HAVE TO COVER
THOUSANDS OF MILES
THROUGH POISONOUS
ATMOSPHERE
BEFORE THEY'D EVER
REACH THE ASYLUM.
AYE, YOU'RE RIGHT.
BUT EVEN IF
THEY MADE IT,
THEY COULDN'T CARRY
ANYTHING POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO BREAK THROUGH
THE ASYLUM DOME.
ONLY THE SHIP HERSELF
COULD DO THAT.
PROBABLY KILL
JIM AND SPOCK.
DOCTOR, THEY MAY
ALREADY BE DEAD.
SLOWLY, DARLING.
SLOWLY.
REST.
IS THIS MORE
OF GARTH'S
PERSUASION, MARTA?
I TOLD HIM I'D DISCOVER
YOUR SECRET.
I LIED.
I WOULD HAVE
TOLD HIM ANYTHING
TO SAVE YOU
FROM THAT TORMENT.
I BELIEVE
YOU MEAN THAT.
I DO.
OH...
THIS IS WHERE
I'VE LONGED TO BE.
I THINK I KNEW
I LOVED YOU
FROM THE MOMENT
I FIRST SAW YOU.
MARTA...
I CAN HELP YOU,
BUT I MUST GET
TO THE "ENTERPRISE'
TO DO THAT.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
OH, YES, IT IS.
IT IS IF I CAN GET
TO THE CONTROL ROOM
AND REMOVE
THE FORCE FIELD.
THEN GARTH
IS FINISHED.
GARTH IS MY LEADER.
HE WILL LEAD YOU
TO DESTRUCTION.
HE'S ALREADY DESTROYED
THE MEDICINE THAT
COULD HAVE HELPED YOU.
BUT THERE'S
MORE MEDICINE
ABOARD THE SHIP.
I'LL HELP YOU,
BUT YOU MUST WAIT.
YOU DO SEE THAT,
DON'T YOU?
SOON, YOUR FRIEND SPOCK
WILL BE HERE, AND THEN--
SPOCK!
AT LEAST I'VE
ARRANGED THAT MUCH.
HOW DID YOU
MANAGE THAT?
A CONVINCING LIE
TOLD TO A GUARD
WHO FINDS ME...
DESIRABLE.
DARLING...
NO, NO.
YOU MUSTN'T STOP ME.
HE'S MY LOVER,
AND I HAVE TO KILL HIM.
SHE SEEMS TO HAVE
WORKED OUT
AN INFALLIBLE METHOD
FOR ENSURING PERMANENT
MALE FIDELITY.
INTERESTING.
I'M VERY GLAD
TO SEE YOU.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE NOW ARMED.
I PRESUME WE SHALL
TRY TO REACH
THE CONTROL ROOM.
YES, YOU PRESUME
CORRECTLY.
THE FORCE FIELD
IS NOW OFF, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
KIRK
TO "ENTERPRISE."
MR. SCOTT,
IT'S THE CAPTAIN.
SCOTT HERE, CAPTAIN.
YOU HAD US WORRIED.
MR. SCOTT, I WANT
A FULLY-ARMED
SECURITY DETAIL
BEAMED DOWN HERE
ON THE DOUBLE.
THEY'RE ALREADY
IN THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM, SIR.
AND HAVE DR. McCOY
PREPARE ADDITIONAL
MEDICINE
AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, I SUGGEST
YOU RETURN TO
THE SHIP AT ONCE.
YOUR SAFETY IS VITAL
TO THE "ENTERPRISE."
Scott: WAITING FOR
YOUR ORDER, CAPTAIN.
I ALSO REQUEST PERMISSION
TO REMAIN HERE
IN CHARGE OF
THE SECURITY TEAM
YOU BEAM DOWN.
VERY WELL.
STILL WAITING,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SCOTT,
THE CAPTAIN'S LIFE
IS IN IMMEDIATE DANGER.
BEAM HIM ABOARD
AT ONCE.
THE SECURITY TEAM
WILL BE ENTRUSTED TO ME.
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3. REPEAT.
QUEEN TO
QUEEN'S LEVEL 3.
HE'S WAITING FOR
THE PROPER REPLY, CAPTAIN.
Scott: GIVE THE
COUNTERSIGN AS ORDERED.
SCOTTY, MR. SPOCK
WILL GIVE
THE COUNTERSIGN.
GIVE HIM THE COUNTERSIGN,
CAPTAIN.
Scotty: SECURITY DETAIL,
STAND BY TO BEAM DOWN.
BLAST AWAY, CAPTAIN,
IF YOU CAN.
YOU THINK
I'M FOOL ENOUGH
TO GIVE YOU
A CHARGED PHASER?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH SPOCK?
WHERE IS HE?
I HAVE DONE NOTHING
WITH HIM AS OF YET,
BUT I DO HAVE
PLANS FOR HIM.
THE VULCAN WILL DIE
RATHER HORRIBLY,
AND HIS DEATH WILL BE
ON YOUR CONSCIENCE.
CAPTAIN GARTH--
LORD GARTH!
NO, SIR.
CAPTAIN GARTH.
STARSHIP FLEET CAPTAIN.
THAT'S
AN HONORABLE TITLE.
AND I WAS THE GREATEST
OF THEM ALL, WASN'T I?
YES, YOU WERE.
YES.
BUT YOU'RE
A SICK MAN NOW, SIR.
I HAVE NEVER BEEN
MORE HEALTHY.
NO. NO, THINK.
THINK BACK
TO WHAT YOU WERE
BEFORE THE ACCIDENT
THAT SENT YOU
TO ANTOS IV.
TRY.
I CAN'T REMEMBER.
IT'S ALMOST
AS IF I HAD DIED
AND WAS REBORN.
NO, I...
I CAN REMEMBER.
YOU...
WERE THE FINEST STUDENT
AT THE ACADEMY,
THE FINEST
STARSHIP CAPTAIN.
YOU WERE
THE PROTOTYPE,
THE MODEL
FOR THE REST OF US.
YES. I DO
REMEMBER THAT.
IT WAS A GREAT
RESPONSIBILITY,
BUT ONE I WAS
PROUD TO BEAR.
AND YOU BORE IT
WELL.
AND THE...DISEASE
THAT CHANGED YOU...
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
AND THE TERRIBLE THINGS
YOU DID SINCE THEN,
YOU'RE NOT TRULY
RESPONSIBLE.
I DON'T WANT
TO HEAR ANYMORE.
YOU'RE WEAK,
AND YOU'RE TRYING
TO DRAIN ME
OF MY STRENGTH.
NO, I'M NOT.
I WANT YOU TO FIND
WHAT YOU ONCE HAD.
I WANT YOU TO GO BACK
TO THE GREATNESS
THAT YOU'VE LOST,
CAPTAIN GARTH.
I AM LORD GARTH,
MASTER
OF THE UNIVERSE.
YOU DOUBT ME ONLY
BECAUSE I HAVE NOT,
AS OF YET,
HAD MY CORONATION.
NO, SIR,
LISTEN TO ME, I--
STOP!
ON YOUR KNEES.
NO.
ON YOUR KNEES
BEFORE ME!
ALL THE OTHERS
BEFORE ME
HAVE FAILED.
ALEXANDER, CAESAR,
NAPOLEON, HITLER,
LEE KWAN, CROTUS.
ALL OF THEM
ARE DUST!
BUT I WILL TRIUMPH.
I WILL MAKE...
THE ULTIMATE
CONQUEST.
THE THRONE
MUST BE HIGHER...
IT MUST BE HIGHER
THAN ANYTHING ELSE
IN THIS ROOM.
HMM...USE THAT TABLE
AS A PEDESTAL.
AH, WELCOME BACK,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
I'M GLAD YOU COULD MAKE IT
FOR THE CORONATION.
CORONATION?
YES. OH, I KNOW
THAT EVEN A REAL THRONE
IS NO MORE
THAN MERELY A CHAIR,
BUT THE SYMBOLISM
IS IMPORTANT,
DON'T YOU AGREE?
YES, I AGREE.
YOU'LL WEAR A CROWN,
TOO, I PRESUME?
THEN AGAIN,
JUST AS A TOKEN.
NOT IMPRESSIVE
IN ITSELF, BUT...
IT WILL SERVE
AS A STANDARD
AROUND WHICH
OUR FOLLOWERS WILL RALLY.
GARTH, YOU HAVE
ONLY A HANDFUL OF MEN.
YOU DO REFUSE
TO ENTER INTO
THE SPIRIT OF THE THING,
DON'T YOU, CAPTAIN?
PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE
A LARGER ROLE
IN THE CEREMONY.
YOU COULD SERVE
AS HUMAN SACRIFICE,
FOR EXAMPLE.
NO, I WOULDN'T
ENJOY THAT AT ALL.
BESIDES, YOU SEEM
TO NEED ME ALIVE.
AH, TRUE.
ALL RIGHT. UH...
HOW ABOUT
CROWN PRINCE?
THAT WOULD MAKE YOU
OUR HEIR APPARENT.
HEIR APPARENT,
I BELIEVE,
IS THE PROPER ROLE
FOR YOU.
BESIDES, WE HAVE
OTHER CANDIDATES
FOR OUR HUMAN
SACRIFICE, HMM?
WHO KNOWS?
READY.
WELL, SINCE THERE IS
NO ONE MIGHTY ENOUGH
TO PERFORM
THIS CEREMONY,
WE'LL PERFORM IT
OURSELVES.
THEREFORE, WE HEREBY
PROCLAIM THAT I AM
LORD GARTH,
MASTER OF THE UNIVERSE.
AND WE DESIGNATE
OUR BELOVED MARTA
TO BE OUR CONSORT.
AND WE FURTHER DESIGNATE
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE"
TO BE OUR HEIR APPARENT.
[APPLAUSE]
AND NOW REMOVE
OUR HEIR APPARENT
THAT WE MAY CONCLUDE
THIS CEREMONY.
LISTEN TO ME.
THIS MAY BE
OUR LAST CHANCE--
GARTH WILL DESTROY
ALL OF US
UNLESS YOU HELP ME
STOP HIM.
AND HE'S USING YOU,
YOU KNOW,
BECAUSE HE WANTS
THE POWER FOR HIMSELF.
I BROUGHT SOMETHING
DOWN HERE THAT MIGHT
HAVE CURED YOU,
BUT HE DESTROYED IT.
IF I CAN GET
A PATROL DOWN HERE,
THEY'D BRING SOME MORE
OF THAT MEDICINE DOWN HERE--
OH!
WELL DONE.
WELL, CAPTAIN,
YOU CONTINUE TO RESIST.
HOW STUPID OF YOU.
PUT HIM IN THAT CHAIR
RIGHT HERE.
I'VE ARRANGED
A SMALL ENTERTAINMENT.
I WOULDN'T WANT HIM
TO MISS ANY OF IT.
WELL, CAPTAIN,
EVEN YOU MUST ADMIT
THAT I'M A GENIUS.
WHAT YOU SEE HERE
IS MY LATEST INVENTION.
THIS IS AN EXPLOSIVE,
THE MOST POWERFUL ONE
IN HISTORY.
IF I WERE TO DROP
THIS FLASK,
THE RESULTING EXPLOSION
WOULD VAPORIZE
THIS PLANET.
NOW DO YOU SEE
WHY IT IS RIDICULOUS
FOR YOU TO RESIST ME,
CAPTAIN?
WELL,
PERHAPS YOU REQUIRE
THE DEMONSTRATION
I'VE ARRANGED.
WATCH CLOSELY.
NOW, IT IS TRUE
THAT SHE IS DEADLY
AS A POISONOUS SERPENT,
BUT SHE IS ALSO
A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN,
AND YOU HAVE HELD HER
IN YOUR ARMS, CAPTAIN.
I'VE ORDERED MY MEN
TO DRIVE HER OUT
OF THE PROTECTIVE DOME.
AND, OF COURSE,
SHE WOULD CHOKE TO DEATH
ON THE OUTSIDE
IN A MATTER OF MINUTES,
BUT I'VE ARRANGED
A MORE MERCIFUL END
FOR HER.
BECAUSE AFTER ALL,
CAPTAIN.
SHE IS MY CONSORT.
ONE TINY CRYSTAL
IMPLANTED
IN HER NECKLACE--
A PORTION
OF THIS EXPLOSIVE
NO BIGGER
THAN A GRAIN OF SAND.
I PROPOSE TO DETONATE
IT FROM HERE.
OH, POOR GIRL.
POOR DEAR,
SUFFERING CHILD.
I WILL HELP HER...
NOW.
THERE'S BEEN
AN EXPLOSION
ON ELBA II.
0.95!
MUST HAVE WIPED OUT
EVERYTHING.
IMMEDIATE PROBE.
IS THE FORCE FIELD
IN PLACE, MR. SULU?
YES, SIR.
SOLIDLY.
LIFE CONTINUES TO EXIST
ON THE PLANET.
GOT TO BREAK
THROUGH IT SOMEHOW.
DOCTOR, I TOLD YOU
WE COULDN'T DO IT
WITHOUT KILLING EVERYONE
IN THE ASYLUM DOME.
I KNOW IT, SCOTTY.
WELL...
THERE'S ONE LAST THING
WE MIGHT TRY.
PERHAPS THE SHIP'S
PHASERS
CAN CUT
THROUGH A SECTION
OF THE FORCE FIELD
AT ITS WEAKEST POINT.
WHERE DID YOU SAY
THAT WAS LOCATED,
MR. SULU?
ON THE FAR SIDE
OF THE PLANET,
MR. SCOTT.
WILL IT LEAVE
A MARGIN OF SAFETY
FOR THE PEOPLE BELOW?
Sulu: YES, SIR.
PREPARE TO CHANGE
ORBITAL PATH, MR. SULU.
ORBITAL COORDINATES
RELEASED, SIR.
BREAK
SYNCHRONOUS ORBIT.
COME TO COURSE 1-4,
MARK 6-8.
COURSE 1-4,
SYNCHRONOUS ORBIT
REESTABLISHED, SIR.
SHIP'S PHASERS
TO NARROW BEAM.
READY, SIR.
LET'S PUNCH A HOLE
IN IT. FULL POWER.
ANOTHER BLAST.
FULL POWER.
FORCE FIELD
STILL HOLDING, SIR.
HERE.
HA HA HA!
HOW ARE YOUR
NERVES, KIRK?
ALL I CAN SAY,
GARTH,
IF IT HAPPENS TO ME,
IT HAPPENS TO YOU.
YOU'RE AN EXTRAORDINARY
FELLOW, KIRK.
YOUR STUBBORNNESS
DEFIES ALL LOGIC.
LOGIC...
THAT IS THE KEY.
YOUR FRIEND SPOCK
IS A LOGICAL MAN...
A VERY LOGICAL MAN.
GO AND BRING THE VULCAN
HERE TO ME.
SPOCK IS NOT ONLY
A MORE LOGICAL MAN
THAN YOU, CAPTAIN.
HE'S A MORE
INTELLIGENT ONE,
I'M SURE.
I SHALL ESTABLISH
A RAPPORT WITH HIM.
[BEEP BEEP BEEP]
FASCINATING.
YOUR VULCAN FRIEND IS
A VERY INGENIOUS FELLOW.
THIS COULD BE
MOST AMUSING.
THAT'S GARTH.
STUN HIM.
HOLD IT, SPOCK.
THAT'S GARTH.
LOOK AT ME
CAREFULLY, SPOCK.
CAN'T YOU TELL
I'M YOUR CAPTAIN?
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3.
I WON'T ANSWER THAT.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT HE WANTS TO KNOW.
VERY CLEVER, GARTH.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ARRANGING TO BEAM DOWN
A SECURITY TEAM.
ARE THERE
ANY OBJECTIONS?
YES. THEY MAY
WALK INTO A TRAP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GARTH CAN DESTROY US.
FASCINATING.
WHAT MANEUVER DID WE USE TO
DEFEAT THE
ROMAN VESSEL NEAR TAU
CETI?
VERY GOOD, SPOCK.
THE COCHRANE
DECELERATION.
SPOCK...
YOU KNOW THE COCHRANE
DECELERATION'S
A CLASSIC
BATTLE MANEUVER.
EVERY STARSHIP CAPTAIN
KNOWS THAT.
AGREED, CAPTAIN...
CAPTAINS.
GENTLEMEN, WHICHEVER
ONE OF YOU
IS CAPTAIN GARTH
MUST AT THIS MOMENT
BE EXPENDING
A GREAT DEAL OF ENERGY
TO MAINTAIN THE IMAGE
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
THAT ENERGY LEVEL
CANNOT BE MAINTAINED
INDEFINITELY,
AND I HAVE TIME.
I'M YOUR CAPTAIN,
SPOCK.
CAN'T YOU TELL?
SHOOT! SHOOT!
HE'S RIGHT, SPOCK.
YOU MUST SHOOT,
BUT YOU MUST SHOOT
BOTH OF US.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO ENSURE THE SAFETY
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
CAPTAIN KIRK,
I PRESUME.
MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK TO "ENTERPRISE."
Scott:
"ENTERPRISE" HERE.
QUEEN TO QUEEN'S
LEVEL 3.
QUEEN TO KING'S
LEVEL ONE.
WILL INTRAMUSCULAR
INJECTION BE
SATISFACTORY?
INTRAVENOUS
IS INDICATED,
UNLESS CIRCUMSTANCES
MAKE IT IMPOSSIBLE.
HOW LONG BEFORE
IT TAKES EFFECT,
DR. McCOY?
REVERSAL OF ARTERIAL
AND BRAIN DAMAGE
SHOULD BEGIN
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
[SOFT HUMMING]
[HUMMING STOPS]
Kirk: CAPTAIN GARTH,
I'M JAMES KIRK.
I'M MR. SPOCK,
SCIENCE OFFICER
ON A STARSHIP.
THE STARSHIP
"ENTERPRISE."
STARSHIP...
STARSHIP.
YES, SIR.
THE "ENTERPRISE."
I'M THE CAPTAIN.
CAN I HELP YOU?
NO, CAPTAIN.
THE MEDICINE SEEMS
TO BE TAKING EFFECT.
I CAN MANAGE.
IT'S VERY
ENCOURAGING.
SHOULD I KNOW YOU, SIR?
NO...
CAPTAIN. NO.
MR. SPOCK?
YES, CAPTAIN.
TELL ME SOMETHING.
WHY WAS IT
SO IMPOSSIBLE
TO TELL THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN US?
IT WAS NOT
IMPOSSIBLE, CAPTAIN.
OUR PRESENCE HERE
IS PROOF OF THAT.
YES, AND--AND
CONGRATULATIONS.
WHAT TOOK YOU
SO LONG?
THE INTERVAL
OF UNCERTAINTY
WAS ACTUALLY FAIRLY
BRIEF, CAPTAIN.
IT ONLY SEEMED
LONG TO YOU.
I WAS WAITING
FOR A VICTOR
IN THE HAND-TO-HAND
STRUGGLE,
WHICH I ASSUMED
WOULD BE
CAPTAIN GARTH.
BECAUSE OF YOUR
DEPLETED CONDITION.
FAILING A RESOLUTION
TO THE STRUGGLE,
I WAS FORCED TO USE
OTHER MEANS
TO MAKE
MY DETERMINATION.
I SEE.
MR. SPOCK, UM...
LETTING YOURSELF
BE HIT ON THE HEAD--
AND I PRESUME YOU
LET YOURSELF BE
HIT ON THE HEAD--
IS NOT EXACTLY
A METHOD
KING SOLOMON
WOULD HAVE APPROVED.
MR. SCOTT,
READY TO BEAM UP.
Scott: AYE, AYE, SIR.