CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5730.2.
THE PLANET ARIANNUS IS VITAL AS
A TRANSFER POINT
ON REGULAR SPACE
COMMERCIAL LANES.
IT HAS BEEN ATTACKED BY
A BACTERIAL INVASION
WHICH THREATENS
TO RENDER IT LIFELESS
UNLESS CHECKED.
OUR MISSION:
TO DECONTAMINATE IT.
MR. CHEKOV, AN ESTIMATED
TIME OF ARRIVAL
FOR ARIANNUS?
AT PRESENT SPEED,
OUR E.T.A. IS
3 HOURS, 4 MINUTES, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ADVISE THE PLANET'S
MINISTRY OF HEALTH
THAT WE'LL BEGIN
DECONTAMINATION
PROCEDURES
IMMEDIATELY UPON
LOCKING INTO ORBIT.
AYE-AYE, SIR.
SCOTTY, WILL THAT
PRESENT ANY PROBLEMS
FOR YOU?
NONE, SIR.
ALL TANKS ARE BEING
POSITIONED.
CAPTAIN, SENSORS
INDICATE A SPACE VEHICLE
OF SOME SORT AHEAD.
IS IT WITHIN VISUAL RANGE?
COMING INTO RANGE
NOW, SIR.
IT'S FOLLOWING
A VERY ERRATIC COURSE.
PUT IT ON THE SCREEN,
EXTREME MAGNIFICATION.
I THINK THAT
MAY BE A STARFLEET
SHUTTLECRAFT, SIR.
THAT IS EXACTLY
WHAT IT IS, MR. CHEKOV.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE ONE
REPORTED STOLEN
FROM STARBASE 4
2 WEEKS AGO.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TRY TO CONTACT THEM ON
COMMAND FREQUENCY 2.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
NO RESPONSE, SIR.
TRY ALL FREQUENCIES.
AYE, SIR. HAILING
ON ALL FREQUENCIES.
CAPTAIN, THERE IS ONE
LIVING CREATURE ABOARD.
HUMANOID.
HE IS EITHER INJURED
OR ILL.
THE CRAFT SHOWS INTERNAL
ATMOSPHERIC LEAKAGE.
THE CREATURE MAY BE
SUFFOCATING.
LIEUTENANT SULU,
ACTIVATE TRACTOR BEAMS.
TRACTOR BEAMS
ACTIVATED.
WE HAVE IT, SIR.
PREPARE TO BRING IT
ABOARD THE HANGAR DECK.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
SEND A SECURITY TEAM
TO THE PRESSURE DOORS
ON THE HANGAR DECK.
AYE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, COME WITH ME.
SCOTTY.
Sulu on P.A.:
HANGAR DOORS OPEN AND CLEARING
FOR ENTRANCE OF SHUTTLECRAFT.
SHUTTLECRAFT APPROACHING
HANGAR DECK.
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
Sulu: BRIDGE TO
CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
HANGAR DOORS
HAVE CLOSED,
AND HANGAR DECK
IS PRESSURIZING.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
WE'LL ENTER AS SOON
AS THE DOORS OPEN,
AND WE'LL GO
ON MY COMMAND.
[HITS FLOOR]
SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION: TO EXPLORE
STRANGE, NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS.
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE NO MAN
HAS GONE BEFORE.
YOU ARE CERTAIN, DOCTOR,
THAT THIS PIGMENTATION
IS THE NATURAL CONDITION
OF THIS INDIVIDUAL?
THAT'S WHAT I'VE RECORDED,
MR. SPOCK.
DO WE HAVE ANY
KNOWLEDGE OF A PLANET
THAT COULD HAVE PRODUCED
SUCH A RACE OF BEINGS?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
BONES, WHAT DO YOU
MAKE OF IT?
WELL, I CAN'T GIVE YOU
ANY SPECIFIC CIRCUMSTANCE
THAT WILL EXPLAIN HIM.
WELL, JUDGING BY
LOOKING AT HIM,
WE KNOW AT THE VERY
LEAST HE IS THE RESULT
OF A VERY DRAMATIC
CONFLICT. SPOCK?
THERE IS NO THEORY,
CAPTAIN,
FROM THE BASIC WORK
OF MENDEL
TO THE MOST RECENT
NUCLEOTIDE STUDIES,
WHICH WOULD EXPLAIN
OUR CAPTIVE.
ALL GRADATIONS OF COLOR
FROM BLACK TO BROWN
TO YELLOW TO WHITE
ARE GENETICALLY
PREDICTABLE.
WE MUST THEREFORE
CONCLUDE THAT
THIS ALIEN
IS THAT OFTEN
UNACCOUNTABLE RARITY,
A MUTATION--
ONE OF A KIND.
YES, I WOULD AGREE
THAT'S THE CASE HERE.
YOUR PROGNOSIS,
DOCTOR?
WELL, I CAN'T
GIVE YOU ONE, JIM.
I'VE NEVER WORKED
ON ANYONE LIKE HIM
OR ANYTHING LIKE HIM.
YET YOU ARE
PUMPING HIM FULL OF
YOUR NOXIOUS POTIONS
AS IF HE WERE A HUMAN.
WHEN IN DOUBT,
THE BOOK PREVAILS,
MR. SPOCK.
I'VE RUN TESTS.
BLOOD IS BLOOD,
EVEN WHEN IT'S GREEN
LIKE YOURS.
THE ORGANS ARE THERE.
THEY'RE REARRANGED
TO A DEGREE,
PLUS A FEW I'VE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
I'VE ENRICHED THE OXYGEN
CONTENT OF HIS BLOOD
AND PUMPED IN
A STRONG STIMULANT.
AND I MUST SAY,
HIS RECUPERATIVE POWERS
APPEAR TO BE EXCELLENT.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
CAPTAIN,
I SHALL DO SOME FURTHER
RESEARCH AND JOIN YOU
ON THE BRIDGE.
HE'S COMING AROUND,
DOCTOR.
WELL...
TOUCH AND GO THERE
FOR A MINUTE,
BUT YOU'RE
OUT OF DANGER NOW.
YOU'RE ABOARD
THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
I'VE HEARD OF IT.
IT'S IN THE UNITED
FLEET OF PLANETS?
FEDERATION.
SO WAS THE SHUTTLECRAFT
THAT YOU WERE FLYING IN.
IT WAS?
DON'T YOU USUALLY
KNOW
WHOSE PROPERTY
YOU'VE STOLEN?
I AM NOT A THIEF.
WELL, CERTAINLY
NO ORDINARY THIEF,
CONSIDERING WHAT
IT IS YOU...
APPROPRIATED.
YOU'RE BEING VERY LOOSE
WITH YOUR ACCUSATIONS,
AND DRAWING CONCLUSIONS
WITHOUT ANY FACTS.
WELL, I DO KNOW
THAT YOU MADE OFF
WITH A SHIP THAT
DIDN'T BELONG TO YOU!
I DO NOT MAKE OFF WITH THINGS.
MY NEED GAVE ME THE RIGHT
TO USE THE SHIP.
MARK THE WORD, SIR--
THE USE OF IT.
YOU CAN TRY THOSE
TECHNICAL EVASIONS
ON STARFLEET
COMMAND.
THAT'S WHERE
YOU'LL BE FACING
YOUR CHARGES.
I'M GRATEFUL FOR
YOUR RESCUE.
DON'T MENTION IT.
WE'RE PLEASED TO
HAVE CAUGHT YOU.
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME IS LOKAI.
GO ON.
FROM THE PLANET
CHERON.
THAT'S IN
THE SOUTHERNMOST PART
OF THE GALAXY,
IN AN UNCHARTED
QUARTER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
SO FAR FROM HOME?
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT WHEN
WE COMPLETE OUR MISSION
WE'LL TAKE YOU TO
STARBASE,
WHERE YOU'LL FACE
A VERY SERIOUS CHARGE.
THE CHARGE IS TRIFLING.
I WOULD HAVE RETURNED
THE SHIP AS SOON AS I...
GO ON. WHAT WERE
YOU GOING TO DO?
YOU MONOTONE HUMANS
ARE ALL ALIKE.
FIRST YOU CONDEMN,
AND THEN ATTACK!
I WILL ANSWER
NO MORE QUESTIONS.
WELL, HOWEVER WE
VIEW HIM, CAPTAIN,
HE'S CERTAINLY
NO ORDINARY SPECIMEN.
WELL, LOKAI,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
NORMAL FOR YOU ,EXACTLY,
BUT IF I HAD YOUR READINGS,
I WOULD BE THE MOST
INCREDIBLE PHYSICAL SPECIMEN
OF ALL TIME.
WE'VE NEVER ENCOUNTERED
A BEING LIKE YOU.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
MORE ABOUT YOU
AND YOUR PLANET.
I'M VERY TIRED.
AND VERY EVASIVE,
OR AT LEAST NOT...
FULLY RESPONSIVE.
NOW, THEN--
I INSIST
I'M EXTREMELY TIRED,
MADE SO BY YOUR VINDICTIVE
CROSS-EXAMINATIONS.
I WILL ANSWER NO MORE
QUESTIONS.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
Intercom: LIEUTENANT
UHURA HERE.
NOTIFY STARBASE 4
THAT WE'VE RECOVERED
ITS SHUTTLECRAFT
AND IT WILL BE RETURNED
ALONG WITH ITS...USER
AS SOON AS WE'VE COMPLETED
OUR MISSION AT ARIANNUS.
AYE, SIR.
OH, BONES, IF YOU'RE SATISFIED
THAT THE MUTATION THEORY
IS APPLICABLE,
I'LL MAKE A NOTE OF IT
IN MY REPORT.
UNLESS WE GET MORE
INFORMATION FROM HIM,
IT'LL HAVE TO SERVE.
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
KIRK HERE.
Chekov: CAPTAIN, CONTACT
WITH ALIEN SHIP, SIR.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
NOTIFY MR. SPOCK.
PUT THE SHIP ON
THE VIEWING SCREEN, MR. SULU.
MAGNIFICATION.
STILL NOTHING,
MR. CHEKOV.
I VERIFY, SIR,
IT'S--IT'S OUT THERE.
[BEEPING]
MAXIMUM MAGNIFICATION.
I DRAW A BLANK, MR. SPOCK.
YOUR RESPONSE?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
NO MALFUNCTION, SIR.
THE READING PERSISTS.
WHAT IS IT?
THERE IS A VESSEL
OUT THERE, CAPTAIN.
COULD IT BE
A ROMULAN SHIP
USING THEIR
CLOAKING DEVICE?
NEGATIVE. THIS WOULD NOT
BE A ROMULAN VESSEL.
IT IS TOTALLY ALIEN
IN CONFIGURATION.
MOTIVE POWER UNKNOWN.
THE SMALL SIZE OF
THE CRAFT INDICATES
A RAPID SCOUT VESSEL,
ONE- OR TWO-MAN CREW.
CAPTAIN? I'VE TRIED
ALL HAILING FREQUENCIES.
NEGATIVE, SIR.
WEAPONRY ON
THE VESSEL, SPOCK?
NOTHING IDENTIFIABLE.
THE CRAFT APPEARS TO BE
BUILT FOR SPEED
RATHER THAN COMBAT.
SOMETHING OUT THERE
CAN'T BE SEEN.
EXPLANATION?
NONE. COMPLETELY ELUSIVE.
IN FACT, IT'S INVISIBLE.
INVISIBLE.
MALFUNCTION?
THERE IS NO SENSOR
FAILURE.
THE READINGS PERSIST.
IT'S HEADED
STRAIGHT FOR US.
EVASIVE ACTION.
[HUM OF ACCELERATION]
IT SHIFTS WITH US,
SIR.
AND WE'RE PUSHING
TO THE LIMIT.
DEFLECTOR SHIELDS ACTIVATED,
MR. SULU.
AUTOMATIC, SIR.
WE'RE ON
COLLISION COURSE!
IT'S OUT OF CONTROL
OR A SUICIDE MISSION.
SOUND ORDER FOR COLLISION.
RED ALERT.
[ALARM]
Sulu: BRACE YOURSELF
FOR COLLISION!
BRACE YOURSELF!
READOUT, MR. SPOCK?
IT JUST...DISINTEGRATED.
FASCINATING.
WHAT IS IT NOW?
IT IS GONE NOW,
CAPTAIN,
BUT IT SEEMS TO HAVE
DEPOSITED AN ALIEN PRESENCE.
WHERE?
Man:
RIGHT HERE, CAPTAIN.
EXPLAIN, SPOCK.
ONE OF A KIND?
I AM BELE.
OF THE PLANET CHERON,
NO DOUBT.
FORGIVE MY UNORTHODOX
ARRIVAL.
YOUR MODE OF TRAVEL
WAS ALSO UNORTHODOX.
SECURE FROM RED ALERT.
WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOUR VEHICLE?
IT SERVED ME LONG
AND DURABLY.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THE STRAIN OF
ARDUOUS PURSUIT
HAS EXCEEDED EVEN ITS
ADVANCED QUALITIES.
I WAS JUST ABLE TO
COMPLETE THIS TRIP
AND DISEMBARK IN TIME,
OR I WOULD HAVE
DISINTEGRATED IN SPACE
WITH IT.
Spock: A MOST
UNIQUE CRAFT.
PITY IT COULDN'T BE
SALVAGED FOR OUR STUDY.
YES, IT WAS SHEATHED
IN SPECIAL MATERIALS
THAT RENDERED IT
INVISIBLE.
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO US?
YOU BEAR PRECIOUS CARGO.
LOKAI.
HE'S TAKEN REFUGE
ABOARD THIS SHIP.
I AM HERE TO CLAIM HIM.
ALL PERSONNEL ABOARD
THIS VESSEL ARE SUBJECT
TO MY COMMAND.
NO ONE CLAIMS ANYONE
WITHOUT DUE PROCESS.
MY APOLOGIES, CAPTAIN.
I OVERSTEP MY POWERS.
"CLAIM" IS UNDOUBTEDLY
AN UNFORTUNATE WORD.
WHAT IS YOUR AUTHORIZATION?
FROM WHAT SOURCE?
I AM CHIEF OFFICER
OF THE COMMISSION
ON POLITICAL TRAITORS.
LOKAI WAS TRIED AND
CONVICTED OF TREASON,
BUT HAD ESCAPED.
MAY I SEE HIM, PLEASE?
HE'S IN SICKBAY.
REMEMBER, SINCE YOU'RE
ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE,
YOU'RE BOUND BY
ITS REGULATIONS.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK.
WELL, LOKAI,
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
THIS TIME I'M SURE
OUR JOINING
WILL BE OF A MORE
PERMANENT NATURE.
CAPTAIN, YOU'RE TO BE
CONGRATULATED.
NEVER BEFORE HAS LOKAI
BEEN RENDERED SO...
QUIESCENT.
I WILL NOT RETURN
TO CHERON WITH HIM!
TO A LAND
OF MURDERING
OPPRESSORS!
I TOLD YOU WHERE
YOU WERE GOING.
I ALLOWED YOUR
FELLOW COUNTRYMAN HERE
SIMPLY AS A COURTESY.
YOU SEE HOW THIS KILLER
REPAYS YOU--
AS HE REPAYS
ALL HIS BENEFACTORS.
BENEFACTORS?
HE'S A LIAR!
HE RAIDED OUR HOMES,
TORE US FROM
OUR FAMILIES,
HERDED US TOGETHER
LIKE CATTLE,
AND THEN SOLD US
AS SLAVES!
THEY WERE SAVAGES,
CAPTAIN.
WE TOOK THEM INTO
OUR HEARTS, OUR HOMES,
WE EDUCATED THEM.
YES--
JUST EDUCATION
ENOUGH TO SERVE
THE MASTER RACE.
YOU WERE THE PRODUCT
OF OUR LOVE!
AND YOU REPAID US
WITH MURDER.
WHY SHOULD A SLAVE SHOW
MERCY TO THE ENSLAVER?
SLAVES? THAT WAS CHANGED
THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO.
YOU WERE FREED.
FREED?
WERE WE FREE TO BE MEN?
FREE TO BE HUSBANDS
AND FATHERS?
FREE TO LIVE OUR LIVES
IN EQUALITY AND DIGNITY?
YES, YOU WERE FREE,
IF YOU KNEW HOW TO USE
YOUR FREEDOM.
YOU WERE FREE ENOUGH
TO SLAUGHTER AND TO BURN
ALL THE THINGS THAT
HAD BEEN BUILT!
I TRIED TO BREAK
THE CHAINS OF
100 MILLION PEOPLE.
MY ONLY CRIME
IS THAT I FAILED.
TO THAT I DO
PLEAD GUILTY.
THERE IS AN ORDER
IN THINGS.
HE ASKS FOR UTOPIA
IN A DAY.
IT CAN'T BE DONE.
NOT IN A DAY.
AND NOT IN 10 TIMES
10,000 YEARS,
BY YOUR THINKING.
TO YOU WE ARE
A LOATHSOME BREED
WHO WILL NEVER
BE READY.
GENOCIDE FOR MY PEOPLE
IS THE PLAN
FOR YOUR UTOPIA!
YOU INSANE, FILTHY
LITTLE PLOTTER OF RUIN!
YOU VICIOUS SUBVERTER
OF EVERY DECENT THOUGHT.
YOU'RE COMING BACK
TO PAY FOR YOUR CRIMES!
I KNOW YOU,
AND ALL THOSE WITH WHOM
YOU'RE PLOTTING TO TAKE
POWER PERMANENTLY.
WHEN I RETURN TO CHERON,
YOU WILL UNDERSTAND
WHAT POWER IS.
I WILL HAVE ARMIES
OF FOLLOWERS!
IT IS NOW VERY CLEAR
THAT YOU KNOW EACH OTHER
EXTREMELY WELL,
GENTLEMEN.
THE ONLY SERVICE
THIS SHIP CAN OFFER IS
TO BRING YOU TOGETHER.
IT IS NOT
A BATTLEFIELD!
CAPTAIN,
I LED REVOLUTIONARIES,
NOT CRIMINALS.
I DEMAND POLITICAL ASYLUM.
THIS SHIP IS
A SANCTUARY.
I'LL TELL YOU
ONCE MORE--
FOR YOU, THIS SHIP
IS A PRISON.
CAPTAIN, IT IS IMPERATIVE
THAT YOU RETURN LOKAI
TO CHERON FOR JUDGMENT.
COMMISSIONER, CHERON
IS NOT A MEMBER
OF THE FEDERATION.
NO TREATIES HAVE
EVER BEEN SIGNED.
YOUR DEMAND FOR
POSSESSION OF
THIS PRISONER
CANNOT BE HONORED.
THERE ARE NO
EXTRADITION
PROCEDURES
TO ALLOW IT.
IS THAT CLEAR,
COMMISSIONER BELE?
CAPTAIN, I HOPE YOU WILL
BE SENSIBLE.
HOW DO YOU MEAN?
COOPERATION.
I CANNOT TAKE SIDES.
SINCE I AM WITHOUT A VESSEL
TO RETURN TO CHERON,
I INSIST THAT YOU
TAKE US THERE IMMEDIATELY.
IMPOSSIBLE. I HAVE
A MISSION TO ACCOMPLISH.
THERE'S A PLANET TO BE
DECONTAMINATED.
MILLIONS OF LIVES ARE
AT STAKE.
ONCE THAT HAS BEEN
COMPLETED, I'LL RETURN
TO STARBASE 4
AND TURN YOU BOTH OVER
TO THE AUTHORITIES.
YOU CAN MAKE YOUR CASE
TO THEM.
I AM SORRY, CAPTAIN.
THAT WILL NOT BE
SATISFACTORY.
NOT AT ALL SATISFACTORY.
COMMISSIONER!
AS A VISITING DIGNITARY
FROM A FAR PLANET,
I OFFER YOU EVERY
HOSPITALITY ABOARD
THIS SHIP.
CHOOSE ANY OTHER COURSE.
YOU ARE THE CAPTAIN.
YES, I AM.
I THINK WE CAN
CONSIDER YOUR PROBLEM...
SETTLED...
AT LEAST
FOR THE PRESENT.
I HAVE ORDERED GUEST QUARTERS
FOR YOU ON DECK 6.
AND I SUGGEST YOU
GET A GREAT DEAL OF REST,
ESPECIALLY YOUR VOCAL CORDS.
IT SEEMS YOU'LL HAVE
A DOUBLE OPPORTUNITY
TO PRACTICE YOUR ORATORY
ON STARBASE 4.
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
Intercom: CHEKOV TO
CAPTAIN KIRK.
CHEKOV TO CAPTAIN KIRK,
URGENT.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE OFF COURSE.
WELL, GET BACK
ON COURSE.
THAT'S JUST IT, SIR.
THE SHIP'S TAKEN A NEW
HEADING ALL BY ITSELF.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
HAVE YOU LOCATED
THE MALFUNCTION?
Sulu: NO, SIR.
THE SHIP IS
UNRESPONSIVE.
WE'RE MOVING AWAY
FROM ARIANNUS.
EXPLANATION,
MR. SPOCK?
ELUSIVE, CAPTAIN.
I AM INVESTIGATING.
I CAN'T
UNDERSTAND IT.
I SIMPLY HAVE
NO CONTROL.
KIRK TO ENGINEERING.
Intercom:
SCOTT HERE.
SCOTTY, WE'RE SUDDENLY
OFF COURSE.
CHECK OUT MANEUVERING
CONTROLS.
AYE, SIR. HOLD.
CAPTAIN? NO MALFUNCTION
INDICATED.
Kirk on intercom:
SWITCH TO AUXILIARY.
AYE, SIR. OUT.
[BEEPING]
ENGINEER TO BRIDGE.
KIRK HERE.
ON AUXILIARY, SIR.
STAND BY FOR CHECK.
SCOTTY, WE'RE STILL
OFF COURSE.
Scotty: I'LL BE
RIGHT UP.
SPEED, MR. CHEKOV.
WE'RE MOVING AT
WARP 8.
AND NEW COURSE?
403 MARK 7.
STRAIGHT FOR
THE COALSACK,
IF THERE IS
NO LETUP.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
PUT THE SHIP ON RED ALERT.
[ALARM]
ALL HANDS, THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN.
THE SHIP
IS ON RED ALERT.
REPEAT, THE SHIP
THERE HAS BEEN
AN UNIDENTIFIED MALFUNCTION IN
THE SHIP'S DIRECTIONAL CONTROL.
REPEAT, THE SHIP IS OFF COURSE
AND OUT OF OUR CONTROL.
OUR NEW HEADING,
MR. CHEKOV?
403 MARK 7.
SPOCK?
CONFIRMED, CAPTAIN.
HOLDING PATTERN.
COORDINATES NOW INDICATE
WE ARE CHARTING COURSE TO--
CAPTAIN, CHERON LIES BETWEEN
403 MARK 7 AND MARK 9.
WE ARE ON THE WAY
TO CHERON.
CAPTAIN, THIS SHIP IS
NOW UNDER MY DIRECTION.
FOR 50,000 OF YOUR
TERRESTRIAL YEARS,
I HAVE BEEN PURSUING LOKAI
THROUGH THE GALAXY.
I HAVE NOT TRAVELED
THIS FAR, THIS LONG,
ONLY TO GIVE HIM UP
NOW.
THIS SHIP GOES WHERE
MY WILL DRIVES IT.
CAPTAIN, WE ARE
NOW AT WARP 10,
AND OUR SPEED
IS INCREASING.
Spock: CAPTAIN,
COURSE IS NOW CLEARLY
STRAIGHT FOR CHERON
DESPITE ALL EFFORTS
TO DIRECT US TO ARIANNUS.
I WILL NOT RETURN
TO CHERON!
CAPTAIN, YOU MUST
GUARANTEE ME SANCTUARY!
HE CANNOT HELP YOU NOW.
YOU ARE LOST, LOKAI.
YOU ARE ON THE WAY
TO JUDGMENT,
TO FINAL PUNISHMENT.
STOP HIM!
NOT THIS TIME,
YOU EVIL MOUND OF FILTH.
NOT THIS TIME.
MY CAUSE IS JUST.
YOU MUST HELP ME.
ALL OF YOU MUST
HELP ME!
THE OLD CRY,
"PITY ME, PITY ME!"
EVERYWHERE HE'S GONE,
HE'S BEEN HELPED
TO ESCAPE.
ON EVERY PLANET,
HE HAS FOUND FOOLS
WHO BLEED FOR HIM
AND SHED TEARS FOR
THE OPPRESSED ONE.
BUT THERE IS NO ESCAPE
FOR YOU ON THIS SHIP.
THIS IS YOUR LAST
SANCTUARY.
KILL HIM.
KILL HIM!
YOU'RE TWO OF
A KIND!
AND WE ARE BOTH
GOING TO CHERON.
YOU CANNOT CHANGE
THE COURSE OF THIS SHIP
ANY MORE THAN YOU
CAN CHANGE ME.
THIS SHIP GOES WHERE
I WANT IT TO GO.
SECURITY, PUT THEM BOTH
IN THE BRIG.
[CRACKLE]
PHASERS ON STUN.
FIRE.
YOUR PHASERS ARE
INEFFECTIVE AGAINST
OUR SHIELDS.
YOU ARE HELPLESS,
CAPTAIN.
WHAT A FOOL I AM,
EXPECTING HELP FROM
SOMEONE LIKE YOU.
THIS SHIP IS GOING
TO ARIANNUS.
NO. THIS SHIP
IS GOING TO CHERON.
I WILL LET NOTHING
INTERFERE.
WE ARE GOING
TO ARIANNUS.
THE LIVES OF
A BILLION PEOPLE
MAKE NO OTHER
CHOICE POSSIBLE.
YOU ARE BEING
OBTUSE, CAPTAIN.
I AM PERMITTING
NO CHOICE.
MY WILL NOW
CONTROLS THIS,
AND NOTHING CAN
BREAK IT.
BELE.
HMM?
I AM CAPTAIN OF
THIS SHIP,
AND IT WILL FOLLOW
WHATEVER COURSE
I SET FOR IT
OR I WILL ORDER
ITS DESTRUCTION.
YOU'RE BLUFFING.
I WILL DESTROY IT.
YOU CAN NO MORE
DESTROY THIS SHIP
THAN I CAN CHANGE COLOR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
TIE IN THE BRIDGE
TO THE MASTER
COMPUTER.
AYE, SIR.
COMPUTER,
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE.
ARE YOU READY
TO COPY?
Computer: WORKING.
PREPARE TO VERIFY
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE
CODE 1.
COMPUTER, THIS IS
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE 1,
CODE 1-1-A.
Computer: VOICE AND CODE 1-1-A
VERIFIED AND CORRECT.
SEQUENCE 1 COMPLETE.
MR. SPOCK?
THIS IS COMMANDER SPOCK,
SCIENCE OFFICER.
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE NUMBER 2,
CODE 1-1-A-2-B.
Computer: VOICE AND CODE
VERIFIED AND CORRECT.
SEQUENCE 2 COMPLETE.
MR. SCOTT?
THIS IS LIEUTENANT
COMMANDER SCOTT,
CHIEF ENGINEERING
OFFICER OF THE
U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE
NUMBER 3,
CODE 1-B-2-B-3.
Computer: VOICE AND CODE
1-B-2-B-3 VERIFIED AND CORRECT.
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE COMPLETED
AND ENGAGED.
AWAITING FINAL CODE
FOR 30-SECOND COUNTDOWN.
MR. SPOCK, HAS THE SHIP
RETURNED TO THE COURSE
SET FOR IT BY MY ORDERS?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
WE ARE STILL HEADED
DIRECTLY FOR CHERON.
Computer:
DESTRUCT SEQUENCE ENGAGED.
AWAITING FINAL CODE
FOR 30-SECOND COUNTDOWN.
COMPUTER, THIS IS
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK OF
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
BEGIN 30-SECOND COUNTDOWN.
CODE ZERO ZERO ZERO
DESTRUCT ZERO.
Computer:
30 SECONDS.
29, 28, 27...
Computer:
25 SECONDS...
LET'S SEE YOU
PREVENT THE COMPUTER
FROM FULFILLING
MY COMMANDS.
Computer:
20 SECONDS...
FROM 5 TO ZERO,
NO COMMAND IN THE UNIVERSE
CAN PREVENT THE COMPUTER
FROM FULFILLING
ITS DESTRUCT ORDERS.
Computer:
15 SECONDS...
YOU CAN USE YOUR WILL TO
DRAG THIS SHIP TO CHERON,
BUT I COMMAND
THE COMPUTER.
MINE IS THE FINAL COMMAND.
10, 9, 8,
7, 6--
I AGREE!
COMPUTER...
THIS IS CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE.
CODE 1-2-3, CONTINUITY.
ABORT DESTRUCT ORDER.
REPEAT,
CODE 1-2-3, CONTINUITY.
ABORT DESTRUCT ORDER.
Computer:
DESTRUCT ORDER ABORTED.
MR. SPOCK, IS THIS SHIP
HEADED FOR ARIANNUS?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
THE ENTERPRISE IS NOW MOVING
IN A CIRCULAR COURSE.
AND AT WARP 10,
WE'RE GOING NOWHERE
MIGHTY FAST.
I WARNED YOU
OF HIS TREACHERY.
KILL HIM!
WE'RE WAITING FOR YOU TO
FULFILL YOUR COMMITMENT,
COMMISSIONER.
CAPTAIN, I AM HAPPY
TO HAVE YOU COMPLETE
YOUR MISSION OF MERCY
TO THE PLANET ARIANNUS.
IT WAS MADNESS TO
INTERFERE WITH SUCH
A WORTHWHILE ENDEAVOR.
BUT IF YOU WILL,
UPON COMPLETION, PLEASE
TAKE ME AND MY TRAITOROUS
CAPTIVE TO CHERON.
I MAKE NO DEALS FOR
CONTROL OF THIS SHIP, SIR.
THE SHIP'S COURSE IS NOW
IN YOUR CONTROL.
SHIP'S COURSE?
ENTERPRISE IS NOW ON COURSE
TO ARIANNUS, CAPTAIN.
SPEED, SCOTTY?
WARP 6 AND SMOOTHLY
OPERATING, SIR.
GOOD.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CANCEL RED ALERT.
AYE, SIR.
LET ME REAFFIRM
MY POSITION, GENTLEMEN.
I COULD PUT YOU
IN THE BRIG FOR WHAT
YOU'VE DONE,
BUT I WON'T DO IT
BECAUSE YOU'RE NEW TO
THIS PART OF THE GALAXY,
WHICH IS GOVERNED BY
THE UNITED FEDERATION
OF PLANETS.
WE LIVE IN PEACE
WITH FULL EXERCISE
OF INDIVIDUAL RIGHTS.
THE NEED TO RESORT
TO VIOLENCE AND FORCE
HAS LONG SINCE PASSED,
AND THEY WILL NOT
BE TOLERATED ABOARD
THIS SHIP.
YOU ARE FREE TO
MOVE ABOUT THE SHIP.
I HOPE THAT YOU'LL
TAKE THE OPPORTUNITY
TO KNOW MORE ABOUT
THE FEDERATION
THROUGH ITS BEST
REPRESENTATIVES--
MY CREW.
BUT LET ME MAKE IT
CLEAR,
I WILL STAND FOR NO
INTERFERENCE
WITH THE FUNCTION
OF THIS SHIP.
ALL HANDS, RETURN
TO NORMAL ROUTINE.
CAPTAIN OUT.
YOU SPEAK VERY WELL,
CAPTAIN.
YOUR WORDS PROMISE
JUSTICE FOR ALL.
WE TRY, SIR.
YES, WELL, I HAVE LEARNED
TO WAIT FOR ACTIONS.
AFTER ARIANNUS,
WHAT IS JUSTICE?
I SHALL WAIT TO SEE IT
DISPENSED.
FASCINATING--
TWO IRREVOCABLY
HOSTILE HUMANOIDS.
DISGUSTING IS WHAT
I CALL THEM.
THAT DESCRIPTION IS NOT
SCIENTIFICALLY ACCURATE.
MR. SPOCK,
THE WORD "DISGUSTING"
DESCRIBES EXACTLY
WHAT I FEEL ABOUT
THOSE TWO.
THAT'S ENOUGH FOR TODAY.
THOSE TWO ARE BEGINNING
TO AFFECT YOU.
AND I KNOW FROM MY ACTIONS
YOU MUST ALL THINK ME
A VOLCANIC HOTHEAD,
ERUPTING LAVA FROM MY NOSTRILS
AT DANGER SIGNALS THAT ARE ONLY
FIGMENTS OF MY IMAGINATION.
BUT BELIEVE ME, MY FRIENDS,
THERE CAN BE NO MOMENT
WHEN I CAN HAVE MY GUARD DOWN
WHERE SUCH AS BELE IS PRESENT.
SO WHAT HAPPENS?
I ACT THE MADMAN
OUT OF THE ANGER AND FRUSTRATION
HE FORCES UPON ME,
AND THEREBY PROVE HIS POINT
THAT I AM A MADMAN.
Sulu:
NO ONE KNOWS HOW HE'LL REACT
UNDER PRESSURE, LOKAI.
Chekov: AFTER ALL,
WE ARE ONLY HUMAN.
Lokai: AH, MR. CHEKOV--
THEREIN LIES MY LACK OF ABILITY
TO ALERT YOU AND YOUR CAPTAIN
TO THE REAL THREAT
OF SOMEONE LIKE BELE.
SEE, YOU ARE FROM
THE PLANET ON EARTH.
THERE IS NO PERSECUTION
ON YOUR PLANET.
HOW CAN YOU UNDERSTAND
MY FEAR,
MY APPREHENSION,
MY DEGRADATION,
MY SUFFERING?
Chekov: THERE WAS PERSECUTION
ON EARTH ONCE.
I REMEMBER READING ABOUT IT
IN MY HISTORY CLASS.
Sulu: YES, BUT IT HAPPENED
WAY BACK IN THE 20th CENTURY.
THERE'S NO SUCH PRIMITIVE
THINKING TODAY.
Lokai: YOU HAVE READ ABOUT IT
IN HISTORY BOOKS.
HOW CAN I MAKE YOUR FLESH
KNOW HOW IT FEELS
TO SEE ALL THOSE
WHO ARE LIKE ME,
AND ONLY BECAUSE THEY ARE,
DESPISED, SLAUGHTERED,
AND EVEN WORSE,
DENIED THE SIMPLEST BIT
OF DECENCY
THAT IS A LIVING BEING'S RIGHT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
IT WOULD BE LIKE
TO BE DRAGGED OUT OF YOUR HOVEL
INTO A WAR ON ANOTHER PLANET?
A BATTLE THAT WILL SERVE
YOUR OPPRESSOR
AND BRING DEATH TO YOU
AND YOUR BROTHERS.
PUTTING THE MATTER
INTO THE HANDS
OF YOUR
STARFLEET COMMAND
IS OF COURSE THE
PROPER PROCEDURE.
HOW LONG WILL IT BE
BEFORE WE HEAR FROM
THEM, CAPTAIN?
I EXPECT THE ANSWER IS
ALREADY ON ITS WAY.
WELL, THEN, LET US
DRINK TO
THEIR WISE SOLUTION
TO OUR PROBLEM.
LET'S DO.
COMMISSIONER,
STARFLEET COMMAND
MAY NOT ARRIVE
AT THE SOLUTION YOU
ANTICIPATE.
THERE IS THE MATTER OF
THE SHUTTLECRAFT WHICH
LOKAI APPROPRIATED.
THE INTERROGATION
OF THAT MATTER MAY BE
OF PARAMOUNT IMPORTANCE
TO STARFLEET.
GENTLEMEN, WE ARE
DISCUSSING A QUESTION
OF DEGREE.
SURELY STEALING
A SHUTTLECRAFT
CANNOT BE EQUATED
WITH THE IMPORTANCE
OF MURDERING THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE.
WE DO NOT KNOW
THAT LOKAI HAS DONE THAT.
ONE THING WE ARE
AGREED ON IS THAT
LOKAI IS A CRIMINAL.
NO, COMMISSIONER,
THE ONE THING WE'VE
AGREED UPON IS THAT
LOKAI TOOK A SHUTTLECRAFT.
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
EXCUSE ME.
Intercom: LIEUTENANT
UHURA TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
I HAVE A COMMUNICATION FROM
STARFLEET COMMAND, SIR.
YES, READ IT.
"STARFLEET COMMAND EXTENDS
GREETINGS TO COMMISSIONER BELE
"OF THE PLANET CHERON.
"HIS URGENT REQUEST TO BE
TRANSPORTED TO HIS PLANET
"WITH THE MAN HE CLAIMS PRISONER
"HAS BEEN TAKEN
UNDER CONSIDERATION.
"IT IS WITH GREAT REGRET THAT
WE CANNOT HONOR THAT REQUEST.
"INTERGALACTIC TREATY
CLEARLY SPECIFIES
"THAT NO BEING CAN BE
EXTRADITED WITHOUT DUE PROCESS.
"IN VIEW OF THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
WE HAVE NO DOUBT
"THAT AFTER A HEARING
AT STARBASE,
"COMMISSIONER BELE WILL BE
PERMITTED TO RETAIN HIS PRISONER
AND WILL BE PROVIDED
TRANSPORTATION--"
THAT'S ENOUGH,
THANK YOU.
AS ALWAYS, LOKAI HAS
MANAGED TO GAIN ALLIES.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE,
COMMISSIONER--
EVEN IF THEY DON'T
RECOGNIZE THEMSELVES
AS BEING SUCH.
YES, HE WILL EVADE,
DELAY, AND ESCAPE AGAIN,
AND IN THE PROCESS
PUT THOUSANDS
OF INNOCENT BEINGS AT
EACH OTHER'S THROATS,
GETTING THEM TO KILL
AND MAIM FOR A CAUSE
WHICH THEY HAVE NO
STAKE IN,
BUT WHICH HE WILL
FORCE THEM TO
VIOLENTLY ESPOUSE
BY TWISTING THEIR MINDS
WITH HIS LIES, HIS
LOATHSOME ACCUSATIONS,
AND HIS FOUL THREATS.
I CAN ASSURE YOU,
COMMISSIONER,
THAT OUR MINDS
WILL NOT BE TWISTED,
NOT BY LOKAI,
NOR BY YOU.
IT IS OBVIOUS TO
THE MOST SIMPLEMINDED
THAT LOKAI IS OF
AN INFERIOR BREED.
Spock: THE OBVIOUS
VISUAL EVIDENCE,
COMMISSIONER,
IS THAT HE IS OF THE SAME
BREED AS YOURSELF.
ARE YOU BLIND,
COMMANDER SPOCK?
WELL, LOOK AT ME.
LOOK AT ME.
YOU'RE BLACK ON ONE SIDE
AND WHITE ON THE OTHER.
I AM BLACK
ON THE RIGHT SIDE.
I FAIL TO SEE
THE SIGNIFICANT
DIFFERENCE.
LOKAI IS WHITE
ON THE RIGHT SIDE.
ALL OF HIS PEOPLE
ARE WHITE ON
THE RIGHT SIDE.
HMM.
COMMISSIONER,
PERHAPS THE EXPERIENCE
OF MY OWN PLANET VULCAN
MAY SET AN EXAMPLE
OF SOME VALUE TO YOU.
VULCAN WAS IN DANGER
OF BEING DESTROYED
BY THE SAME CONDITIONS
AND CHARACTERISTICS
WHICH THREATEN
TO DESTROY CHERON.
WE WERE ONCE A PEOPLE
LIKE YOURSELVES--
WILDLY EMOTIONAL,
OFTEN COMMITTED TO
IRRATIONALLY OPPOSING
POINTS OF VIEW,
LEADING, OF COURSE,
TO DEATH AND DESTRUCTION.
ONLY THE DISCIPLINE
OF LOGIC SAVED MY PLANET
FROM EXTINCTION.
COMMANDER SPOCK,
I AM DELIGHTED THAT
VULCAN WAS SAVED,
BUT YOU CANNOT EXPECT
LOKAI AND PEOPLE
LIKE HIM
TO ACT WITH
SELF-DISCIPLINE
ANY MORE THAN
YOU CAN EXPECT A PLANET
TO STOP ORBITING
ITS SUN.
LET LOKAI STATE
HIS GRIEVANCES.
HEAR HIM.
LISTEN TO HIM.
MAYBE HE CAN CHANGE.
MAYBE HE WANTS--
THEY CANNOT CHANGE.
CHANGE IS THE ESSENTIAL
PROCESS OF ALL EXISTENCE.
FOR INSTANCE,
THE PEOPLE OF CHERON
MUST HAVE ONCE
BEEN MONO-COLORED.
YOU MEAN LIKE
BOTH OF YOU?
THERE MUST HAVE BEEN A TIME--
LONG AGO, NO DOUBT--
WHEN THAT WAS TRUE.
[SHIP'S WHISTLE]
EXCUSE ME.
KIRK HERE.
Scotty: WE'RE ORBITING
ARIANNUS, SIR.
VERY GOOD.
COMMENCE DECONTAMINATION
PROCEDURES WHEN READY,
ADVISE WHEN COMPLETE.
AT ONCE, SIR.
SCOTT OUT.
I ONCE HEARD THAT
ON SOME OF YOUR PLANETS,
PEOPLE BELIEVE THEY ARE
DESCENDED FROM APES.
THE ACTUAL THEORY IS
THAT ALL LIFEFORMS
EVOLVED FROM THE LOWER LEVELS
TO THE MORE ADVANCED STAGES.
READY FOR DECONTAMINATION
PROCEDURE.
READY, SIR.
READY HERE.
READY, MR. SCOTT.
MR. SULU, LOCK
INTO COORDINATED
REQUESTED BY ARIANNUS.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
MR. CHEKOV,
POSITION TANKS
FOR SPRAY RELEASE.
TANKS POSITIONED.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ADVISE ARIANNUS
THE MISSION IS
TO BEGIN ON SIGNAL.
ALL GROUND PRECAUTIONS
MUST BE READY.
ARIANNUS SAYS,
"GO AHEAD."
WELL, LET HER RIP.
SCOTT TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
Intercom:
KIRK HERE.
FIRST RUN COMPLETE,
SIR.
GOOD. REPEAT PROCEDURE
FOR MAXIMUM EFFECT.
AYE, SIR.
READY TO REPEAT
DECONTAMINATION PROCEDURE.
READY, SIR.
MR. SULU.
READY HERE.
KIRK HERE.
WE'RE COMPLETING
THE FINAL ORBIT
OF ARIANNUS, SIR.
I'M AWAITING INSTRUCTIONS
TO SET COURSE FOR
THE NEXT DESTINATION.
VERY GOOD.
WE'LL BE RIGHT UP.
SET DIRECTIONAL CONTROLS
FOR STARBASE 4.
KIRK OUT.
WILL YOU JOIN US
ON THE BRIDGE?
THERE IS NOTHING
I WOULD LIKE MORE.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5730.7.
HAVING COMPLETED
OUR MISSION TO ARIANNUS,
THE ENTERPRISE IS NOW
ON COURSE TO STARBASE 4.
THE CREW IS ON NORMAL ROUTINE,
AND WE ARE PROCEEDING
WITHOUT INCIDENT.
TROUBLE, MR. CHEKOV?
I DON'T RIGHTLY KNOW,
MR. SPOCK.
I WAS TRYING TO PROGRAM
FOR STARBASE 4 AS ORDERED.
I CAN'T GET A RESPONSE.
IT JUST SEEMED
TO GO DEAD, SIR.
CAPTAIN, SOME OF
THE MEMORY BANKS
OF THE COMPUTER
ARE BURNED OUT.
CAN YOU DETERMINE
WHICH ONES?
THE DIRECTIONAL CONTROL
AND THE SELF-DESTRUCT, CAPTAIN,
ARE BOTH BURNT OUT.
I DID IT LIKE THIS.
[CRACKLING]
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5730.6.
IN A DELIBERATE ACT OF SABOTAGE,
COMMISSIONER BELE HAS BURNED OUT
OUR DESTRUCT MECHANISM
AND THROUGH THE POWER
OF HIS WILL HAS AGAIN TAKEN OVER
DIRECTIONAL CONTROL
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
NOW CAN WE GO TO CHERON
WITHOUT ANY MORE DISCUSSION?
AT THE MOMENT, I SEEM
TO HAVE NO CHOICE.
SO THIS IS JUSTICE
AFTER ARIANNUS!
YOU HAVE SIGNED
MY DEATH WARRANT.
I WARNED YOU
WHAT TO EXPECT.
BUT YOU CONTINUE TO LET
THIS MOCKERY OF JUSTICE
GO ON?
IF YOU ARE PARTISANS
OF JUSTICE, PROVE IT.
KILL HIM!
Chekov: WE ARE
NOT KILLERS.
THEN WHAT DO YOU DO?
CARRY JUSTICE ON YOUR TONGUES?
YOU WILL BEG FOR IT,
BUT YOU WON'T FIGHT
OR DIE FOR IT!
AFTER SO MANY YEARS
OF LEADING THE FIGHT,
YOU SEEM VERY MUCH ALIVE.
I DOUBT THAT THE SAME
CAN BE SAID FOR MANY
OF HIS FOLLOWERS.
YOU'RE FINISHED, LOKAI!
OH, WE'VE GOT YOUR KIND
PENNED IN ON CHERON
INTO LITTLE DISTRICTS,
AND IT'S NOT GOING
TO CHANGE.
YOU'VE COMBED THE GALAXY
AND COME UP WITH NOTHING
BUT MONO-COLORED TRASH,
DO-GOODERS,
AND BLEEDING HEARTS.
YOU'RE DEAD,
YOU HALF-WHITE!
YOU USELESS PIECES
OF BLAND FLESH.
I'LL TAKE YOU WITH ME,
YOU HALF-BLACK!
[CRACKLING]
BELE!
YOU KEEP THIS UP, AND YOU'LL
NEVER GET TO CHERON
WITH YOUR PRISONER.
THE BRIDGE OF THIS SHIP WILL BE
IRREPARABLY DAMAGED!
THIS WILL BE
YOUR FINAL BATTLEFIELD!
YOUR 50,000 YEARS OF PURSUIT
WILL HAVE BEEN WASTED!
AND YOU, LOKAI--
YOU'LL DIE HERE IN SPACE.
YOU'LL INSPIRE
NO MORE DISCIPLES.
YOUR CAUSE WILL BE ENDED!
REMEMBER, CAPTAIN--
POLITICAL SANCTUARY
IS MY RIGHT!
I AM YOUR PRISONER.
HONOR THAT RIGHT,
OR THE FIGHT WILL
GO ON
AND YOUR SHIP
WILL BURN UP!
YOU'VE MADE YOUR POINT.
IF YOU LISTEN TO
HIS LEGALISTIC TRICKERY,
I SHALL HAVE TO
DESTROY THIS SHIP
AND EVERYBODY ABOARD!
I UNDERSTAND.
WILL YOU RETURN THE ENTERPRISE
TO MY CONTROL?
WHY NOT?
SCOTTY, HAVE REPAIRS
ON DIRECTIONAL CONTROL
BEEN COMPLETED?
AYE, SIR.
REROUTED.
CHECK CONTROLS
AND COORDINATES.
Sulu: CONTROLS
OPERATING, CAPTAIN.
THE ENTERPRISE
IS RESPONDING
AS ALWAYS.
CAPTAIN,
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
Chekov: LOCKING
ONTO COORDINATES.
CAPTAIN, WE ARE WITHIN
SCANNING RANGE OF CHERON.
IS IT WITHIN
VISUAL RANGE?
COMING WITHIN VISUAL RANGE
NOW, CAPTAIN.
CHEKOV, PUT IT ON THE SCREEN,
EXTREME MAGNIFICATION.
WHAT ARE YOU PICKING UP?
SEVERAL VERY LARGE CITIES,
UNINHABITED.
EXTENSIVE TRAFFIC SYSTEMS,
BARREN OF TRAFFIC.
LOWER ANIMALS AND VEGETATION
ENCROACHING ON THE CITIES.
NO SAPIENT LIFEFORMS
REGISTERING AT ALL,
CAPTAIN.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE OF
NATURAL DISASTER,
YET THERE ARE VAST NUMBERS
OF UNBURIED CORPSES
IN ALL CITIES.
YOU MEAN...
ALL THE PEOPLE ARE DEAD?
ALL DEAD, CAPTAIN.
THEY HAVE ANNIHILATED
EACH OTHER--TOTALLY.
MY PEOPLE...ALL DEAD?
YES, COMMISSIONER.
ALL OF THEM.
NO ONE ALIVE?
NONE AT ALL, SIR.
YOUR BAND OF MURDERERS
DID THIS!
YOU GENOCIDAL
MANIAC!
Kirk: STOP IT!
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU TWO?
DIDN'T YOU HEAR SPOCK?
YOUR PLANET IS DEAD!
THERE'S NOBODY ALIVE
ON CHERON BECAUSE OF HATE.
THE CAUSE YOU FOUGHT ABOUT
NO LONGER EXISTS.
GIVE YOURSELVES TIME TO BREATHE,
GIVE UP YOUR HATE!
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO LIVE WITH US.
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU BOTH MUST END UP DEAD
IF YOU DON'T STOP HATING.
YOU'RE AN IDEALISTIC
DREAMER.
BELE...
THE CHASE IS FINISHED.
HE MUST NOT ESCAPE ME.
WHERE CAN HE GO?
BELE...
SHALL I ALERT
SECURITY, SIR?
NO, LIEUTENANT.
WHERE CAN THEY RUN?
Spock: CAPTAIN,
I HAVE LOCATED THEM
ON SHIP SENSORS.
BELE IS CHASING LOKAI...
ON DECK 3.
BELE IS PASSING
RECREATION ROOM 3,
APPROACHING
THE CREWMEN'S LOUNGE.
LOKAI IS RUNNING
PAST THE CREWMAN'S LOUNGE.
LOKAI HAS JUST ARRIVED
ON DECK 5.
PASSING RECREATION ROOM 3.
CAPTAIN, SOMEONE
HAS ACTIVATED THE
TRANSPORTER MECHANISM.
SPOCK, ANYONE IN
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
TRANSPORTER ROOM IS CLEAR.
HOWEVER, THERE IS A LIFEFORM
MATERIALIZING ON THE PLANET.
IT IS LOKAI.
HE IS BACK ON CHERON.
THERE'S NOBODY THERE
TO TRY HIM.
HIS JUDGES ARE
ALL DEAD.
CAPTAIN, THE TRANSPORTER
MECHANISM HAS BEEN
ACTIVATED AGAIN.
OF COURSE.
IT IS BELE, CAPTAIN.
AND ANOTHER LIFEFORM
HAS APPEARED ON CHERON.
IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
TO EXPECT SENSE FROM
TWO MENTALITIES OF SUCH
EXTREME VIEWPOINTS
IS NOT LOGICAL.
BUT THEIR PLANET'S
DEAD.
DOES IT MATTER NOW
WHICH ONE'S RIGHT?
NOT TO LOKAI AND BELE.
ALL THAT MATTERS TO THEM
IS THEIR HATE.
DO YOU SUPPOSE THAT'S
ALL THEY EVER HAD, SIR?
NO.
BUT THAT'S ALL
THEY HAVE LEFT.
WARP FACTOR 2,
MR. SULU.
SET COURSE FOR
STARBASE...4.