CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5423.4.
WE ARE ORBITING
THE PLANET GIDEON,
WHICH IS STILL NOT A MEMBER
OF THE UNITED FEDERATION
OF PLANETS.
THE TREATY NEGOTIATIONS
HAVE BEEN DIFFICULT
BECAUSE GIDEON HAS CONSISTENTLY
REFUSED THE PRESENCE
OF A DELEGATION
FROM THE FEDERATION
ON ITS SOIL
OR ANY SURVEILLANCE
BY THE SHIP'S SENSORS.
THEY HAVE FINALLY AGREED
TO A DELEGATION OF ONE.
THEY INSISTED IT BE THE CAPTAIN
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
I AM THEREFORE
BEAMING DOWN AT ONCE.
IT'S TOO BAD
GIDEON ISN'T CLEARED
FOR GENERAL
VISITATION,
MR. SPOCK.
ACCORDING TO
THE PHYSIO-CULTURAL
REPORTS SUBMITTED
TO THE FEDERATION,
IT'S A VIRTUAL PARADISE.
I SHALL BE INTERESTED
IN HEARING YOUR
DESCRIPTION, CAPTAIN.
YOU WON'T HAVE
LONG TO WAIT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
DO WE HAVE
FINAL CLEARANCE
FROM GIDEON?
YES, MR. SPOCK.
THEY HAVE PROVIDED US
WITH THE COORDINATES
FOR BEAM-DOWN.
MAY I HAVE THEM,
PLEASE?
875.
020.
079.
LET'S GO,
MR. SPOCK.
ENERGIZING.
MR. SPOCK?
MR. SPOCK, I HAVE NOT
YET TRANSPORTED DOWN.
WHY DID YOU LEAVE YOUR POST
BEFORE CONFIRMING TRANSPORT?
MR. SPOCK?
SPOCK?
ENGINEERING.
MR. SCOTT?
SCOTTY?
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
REPORT IMMEDIATELY.
ALL BRIDGE PERSONNEL,
KIRK TO CREW.
IS ANYONE ABOARD?
SICK BAY. DR. McCOY.
BONES?
BONES, ANSWER ME.
BONES.
STILL ORBITING GIDEON.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk, voice-over: I AM ALONE
ON THE "ENTERPRISE."
I HAVE SEARCHED
EVERY AREA OF THE SHIP
AND STILL CANNOT FIND
A TRACE OF THE CREW
OR AN INDICATION OF HOW
ITS DISAPPEARANCE WAS MANAGED.
THE ONE THING
THAT IS OBVIOUS
IS THAT I SUFFERED
A MEMORY LAPSE
DURING WHICH TIME
I BRUISED MY ARM.
IT IS CAUSING ME
SOME IRRITATION.
GIDEON IS CONTACTING
US, MR. SPOCK.
PUT IT ON THE SCREEN.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN KIRK?
THIS IS AMBASSADOR HODIN.
THE COUNCIL IS STILL
AWAITING YOUR ARRIVAL.
THIS IS MR. SPOCK,
AMBASSADOR HODIN.
CAPTAIN KIRK WAS
TRANSPORTED DOWN
MINUTES AGO.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I TRANSPORTED
HIM MYSELF.
HE NEVER ARRIVED.
HE WAS BEAMED DIRECTLY
TO YOUR COUNCIL CHAMBERS.
PLEASE VERIFY
YOUR COORDINATES.
875...
020...
079.
COORDINATES
CONFIRMED.
WE GAVE YOU
THE EXACT COORDINATES
WHICH SHOULD HAVE BROUGHT
CAPTAIN KIRK DIRECTLY
INTO THIS VERY ROOM.
I AM NOT QUESTIONING
THAT, SIR.
IF HE'S NOT HERE,
THAT IS YOUR OWN RESPONSIBILITY,
MR. SPOCK
AND THAT OF YOUR STAFF.
I DO NOT DENY
THAT, SIR.
I AM NOT ATTEMPTING
TO BLAME YOUR PERSONNEL.
WE ARE GLAD
TO HEAR THAT.
WE SHALL HAVE TO ENTER IT
INTO THE RECORDS
OF THIS MOST
UNFORTUNATE EVENT.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
EVEN WITH INTRICATE
MACHINERY
AS DELICATELY
BALANCED AS OURS,
THERE IS STILL
A MARGIN FOR ERROR
WHICH MUST
BE DEALT WITH.
IT IS POSSIBLE
THAT CAPTAIN KIRK
MATERIALIZED
ON SOME OTHER PART
OF GIDEON.
LET US HOPE IT WAS
ON DRY LAND.
YOUR EXCELLENCY--
MAY I CUT RIGHT
TO THE HEART
OF THE MATTER?
I REQUEST PERMISSION
TO BEAM DOWN
TO CONDUCT
THE SEARCH
FOR OUR CAPTAIN.
PERMISSION DENIED.
YOUR FEDERATION
MUST BE AWARE
OF OUR JEALOUS TRADITION
OF ISOLATION FROM ALL
CONTAMINATING CONTACTS
WITH THE VIOLENT NATURE
OF PLANETS
OF OTHER STAR SYSTEMS.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
THE WARS
BETWEEN OPPOSING
STAR SYSTEMS
NO LONGER PREVAIL
IN OUR GALAXY.
IF YOU WILL GRANT
PERMISSION--
OF COURSE, WE SHALL INSTITUTE
A THOROUGH SEARCH.
IN THE MEANTIME,
MR. SPOCK,
I SUGGEST THAT YOU LOOK
TO YOUR MACHINERY.
WE MUST ACKNOWLEDGE
ONCE AND FOR ALL
THAT THE PURPOSE
OF DIPLOMACY IS
TO PROLONG A CRISIS.
McCoy: WHAT ARE WE WAITING
FOR, MR. SPOCK?
WE'RE NOT DIPLOMATS!
WE ARE REPRESENTATIVES
OF THE FEDERATION,
DOCTOR.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN
THAT WE HAVE TO BEHAVE
LIKE CHILDREN
AND LISTEN
TO SOME FOOL LECTURE
BY A DIPLOMAT.
UNFORTUNATELY, DIPLOMACY
IS THE ONLY CHANNEL
AVAILABLE TO US
AT THE MOMENT.
THE PLANET IS SHIELDED
FROM OUR SENSORS.
THEREFORE,
WE CANNOT SCAN IT.
THEREFORE WE ARE UNABLE
TO SELECT COORDINATES.
THEY MUST BE PROVIDED
BY GIDEON.
WE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE AGREED TO
SUCH RESTRICTIONS.
Spock: WE DID NOT,
MR. CHEKOV.
THE FEDERATION DID.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
CONTACT STARFLEET
IMMEDIATELY.
EXPLAIN OUR PROBLEM.
REQUEST PERMISSION TO USE
EVERY MEANS AT OUR DISPOSAL
TO PRESS THE SEARCH
FOR CAPTAIN KIRK.
AT ONCE, SIR.
Chekov:
ARE THERE ANY OTHER
POSSIBILITIES?
THERE ARE ENDLESS,
MR. CHEKOV.
McCoy: WHERE DO WE
START, MR. SPOCK?
INSTITUTE
A SENSOR SCAN
360 DEGREES,
ONE DEGREE
AT A TIME.
YOU MEAN YOU'RE GOING
TO SCAN SPACE FOR HIM?
BUT, SIR, THAT COULD
TAKE YEARS.
THEN THE SOONER
YOU BEGIN,
THE BETTER.
AYE, SIR.
[DOOR OPENS]
WHO ARE YOU?
ODONA.
YES. MY NAME
IS ODONA.
WHY DID YOU
BRING ME HERE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
ON MY SHIP?
IS THIS ENTIRE SHIP
YOURS?
NOT MY PERSONAL
PROPERTY,
BUT I'M THE CAPTAIN.
OH! AND YOU HAVE IT
ALL TO YOURSELF?
IT SEEMS,
AT THE MOMENT,
WE HAVE IT ALL
TO OURSELVES.
OH!
YOU'RE HURTING ME,
CAPTAIN--
KIRK. I'M SORRY.
JAMES KIRK.
AND I DIDN'T
BRING YOU HERE.
IF YOU DIDN'T
BRING ME HERE--
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHO HAS BROUGHT
YOU HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU...
WHAT HAPPENED BEFORE
YOU CAME HERE?
TRY TO REMEMBER.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
IT SEEMS I WAS
STANDING IN A--
YES, I WAS STANDING
IN A LARGE AUDITORIUM
CROWDED WITH PEOPLE--
THOUSANDS PRESSED
IN AGAINST ME.
I COULD HARDLY
BREATHE.
I WAS FIGHTING
FOR OXYGEN,
SCREAMING
TO GET OUT.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
I'M NOT.
BUT YOU ARE TROUBLED.
I SEEM TO BE
THE ONLY ONE
OF MY CREW
LEFT ON BOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE."
430,
AND I APPARENTLY AM
THE ONLY ONE LEFT.
I'M SORRY.
I WISH I COULD HELP.
MAYBE YOU CAN.
TELL ME THE REST.
YOU WERE FIGHTING
FOR OXYGEN,
SCREAMING TO GET
OUT OF THERE.
AND THEN SUDDENLY
I WAS HERE ON THIS--
ON YOUR SHIP,
AND THERE WAS
ALL THIS SPACE
AND FREEDOM.
I JUST WANTED
TO FLOAT.
AND THEN,
THERE YOU WERE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
ABOARD THE "ENTERPRISE"?
I DON'T KNOW.
NOT LONG.
IS IT IMPORTANT?
IT MIGHT BE.
COME WITH ME.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
HAS STARFLEET
HONORED OUR REQUEST
WITH A REPLY?
THERE'S BEEN
NO RESPONSE
AS YET, SIR.
DID YOU ADVISE THEM
THAT THE CAPTAIN'S
LIFE IS AT STAKE?
YES, SIR. THEY INSIST
THE MATTER MUST BE REFERRED
TO THE FEDERATION.
WHAT DEPARTMENT?
THE BUREAU
OF PLANETARY TREATIES.
CONTACT THEM DIRECTLY.
I DID, MR. SPOCK.
THEY INSIST THAT
WE MUST GO THROUGH
STARFLEET CHANNELS.
WITH THE CAPTAIN
LOST SOMEWHERE,
THAT'S THE BEST
THEY COULD COME UP WITH?
DIPLOMATS
AND BUREAUCRATS
MAY FUNCTION
DIFFERENTLY,
BUT THEY ACHIEVE EXACTLY
THE SAME RESULTS.
NINE MINUTES OF MY LIFE
HAS BEEN LOST.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
BETWEEN THE TIME I TRIED
TO BEAM DOWN TO GIDEON
AND I FOUND
MYSELF HERE ALONE,
9 MINUTES HAVE DISAPPEARED,
JUST LIKE THAT.
NOW, WHAT HAPPENED
DURING THOSE 9 MINUTES?
WHAT IS GIDEON?
THAT'S YOUR HOME.
THE PLANET
THAT YOU COME FROM.
IS IT?
WELL, IT MUST BE.
GIDEON? I DON'T KNOW
ANY GIDEON.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
WE WERE IN
SYNCHRONOUS ORBIT
OVER THE CAPITAL CITY
OF GIDEON.
I TRIED TO BEAM DOWN.
SOMETHING HAPPENED.
AND YOU WERE BEAMED
ABOARD FROM GIDEON.
OH, I DO NOT
THINK SO.
WE'RE NO LONGER
OVER GIDEON.
WHERE ARE WE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THAT QUADRANT.
ODONA, YOU MUST REALIZE
THAT WE'RE NOT
HERE BY ACCIDENT.
SOME FORCE,
SOME INTELLIGENCE
HAS ARRANGED THIS--
FOR A PURPOSE.
CAPTAIN.
BEFORE, I SAID
I WASN'T AFRAID.
NOW I AM.
THE AMBASSADOR
WILL SPEAK, SIR.
THEY'RE REQUESTING
VISUAL COMMUNICATION.
GOOD NEWS. VERY GOOD NEWS
INDEED, MR. SPOCK.
YOUR CAPTAIN IS
DEFINITELY NOT ON GIDEON.
AS YOU REQUESTED, WE MADE
A MOST THOROUGH SEARCH,
AND YOU WILL BE
RELIEVED TO KNOW
THAT YOU MAY NOW INVESTIGATE
ALL THE OTHER POSSIBILITIES
AND FORGET ABOUT GIDEON.
BUT THAT IS NOT
WHAT WE REQUESTED.
YOU REQUESTED
A MOST THOROUGH SEARCH.
IT IS IN THE RECORD,
AND WE HAVE USED
EVERY MEANS AT OUR DISPOSAL
TO ACCOMMODATE YOU.
YOUR RECORD
ON THE SUBJECT
IS NOT PRECISE,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
SURELY, MR. SPOCK,
YOU DO NOT INTEND,
I HOPE, TO CREATE
A DISPUTE BETWEEN
THE FEDERATION
AND GIDEON.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
A DISPUTE IS
THE FARTHEST THING
FROM OUR MINDS,
AND THERE'S NO NEED
TO CHECK YOUR RECORDS.
I MERELY SUGGEST
THAT THE LANGUAGE
OF OUR STATEMENT
MAY NOT HAVE BEEN
UNDERSTOOD
EXACTLY AS INTENDED.
MR. SPOCK, YOU ARE
AN OFFICER OF A SPACESHIP.
IN YOUR PROFESSION,
YOU USE MANY INSTRUMENTS,
TOOLS, AND WEAPONS
TO ACHIEVE
YOUR OBJECTIVES.
TRUE,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
HOWEVER, THE ONLY TOOL
DIPLOMACY HAS IS LANGUAGE.
IT IS
OF THE UTMOST IMPORTANCE
THAT THE MEANING BE
CRYSTAL CLEAR.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
I AM BASICALLY
A SCIENTIST.
CLARITY OF FORMULATION
IS ESSENTIAL
IN MY PROFESSION ALSO.
I'M GLAD TO HEAR IT.
PERHAPS YOU COULD THEN
MAKE GREATER EFFORT
TO CHOOSE YOUR WORDS
MORE PRECISELY.
ARE YOU GOING
TO LET HIM GET
AWAY WITH THAT?
NO MATTER WHAT YOU SAY,
MR. SPOCK, HE'LL TWIST
YOUR MEANING.
YES. HE'S
INFURIATING, SIR.
HOW CAN YOU
STAND IT?
WE CANNOT LEAVE
WITHOUT BEING
ABSOLUTELY SURE
OURSELVES
THAT EVERYTHING
HAS BEEN DONE.
NOW, CERTAINLY
YOU UNDERSTAND OUR
FEELINGS ABOUT THAT.
MR. SPOCK? MR. SPOCK?
YES, YOUR EXCELLENCY.
ARE YOU STILL THERE?
THERE WAS CONSIDERABLE
INTERFERENCE WITH
YOUR TRANSMISSION.
A LOT OF NOISE
DROWNED OUT WHAT WAS SAID.
WOULD YOU REPEAT, PLEASE?
I APOLOGIZE
FOR THE NOISE,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
TO SUMMARIZE, I REQUEST
PERMISSION TO TRANSPORT
DOWN TO GIDEON.
FORGIVE ME, MR. SPOCK.
NO CRITICISM OF YOUR
EQUIPMENT WAS INTENDED,
BUT IT HAS SENT YOUR CAPTAIN
ON SOME STRANGE JOURNEY--
A SAFE ONE,
WE ALL STILL HOPE,
BUT IT COULD CREATE
FOR US SERIOUS INCIDENTS
WITH YOUR FEDERATION,
AND NOW YOU PROPOSE
TO REPEAT THIS DISASTER
WITH ANOTHER OFFICER?
THIS WOULD BE MADNESS.
I'LL NOT TAKE THAT,
MR. SPOCK!
THAT TRANSPORTER
WAS IN PERFECT
CONDITION.
I GUARANTEE THAT
MYSELF.
TRANSPORT ME DOWN
RIGHT THIS MINUTE,
AND I'LL PROVE
TO THOSE--
GENTLEMEN--
MR. SCOTT, YOU'LL GO
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
AND AWAIT MY ORDERS.
AYE, MR. SPOCK.
[MUTTERING]
I COULD NOT QUITE
MAKE THAT OUT, MR. SPOCK.
WOULD YOU BE SO GOOD
AS TO REPEAT WHAT YOU SAID?
YES, YOUR
EXCELLENCY.
THE SHIP'S ENGINEER
WAS EXPLAINING
THAT THE MALFUNCTION
WHICH DID EXIST
HAS NOW BEEN REPAIRED.
WE WOULD APPRECIATE
AN OPPORTUNITY TO TEST
THE EQUIPMENT.
I THEREFORE
REQUEST PERMISSION
TO BEAM DOWN
TO YOUR COUNCIL CHAMBER.
BUT, MR. SPOCK, YOU--
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
GRANT THIS ONE REQUEST.
YOU ARE A VERY PERSISTENT
FELLOW, MR. SPOCK.
VERY WELL, THEN.
YOU SHALL TEST THE SKILL
OF YOUR VERY EXCITABLE
REPAIRMAN.
THERE IS ONE PROVISO.
WE CANNOT RISK
FURTHER INCIDENTS.
YOU WILL THEREFORE
TRANSPORT A MEMBER
OF MY STAFF TO YOUR SHIP.
LET US FIRST SEE
IF THAT WORKS.
THANK YOU,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
YOUR PROPOSAL
IS ACCEPTED.
MR. SCOTT.
SCOTT HERE.
PREPARE TO BEAM ABOARD
A REPRESENTATIVE
OF THE GIDEON COUNCIL.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
MY ASSISTANT WILL PROVIDE
YOU WITH THE PROPER--
WHAT IS THE WORD?
Spock: COORDINATES.
THANK YOU.
PROCEED, KRODAK.
875...
Scott: 875...
020...
Krodak: 709.
709.
ENERGIZING.
MR. SPOCK, THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GIDEON IS HERE.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
YOUR ASSISTANT
HAS ARRIVED SAFELY,
AND I AM NOW READY TO
TRANSPORT DOWN TO GIDEON.
NOW, NOW, NOT SO FAST,
MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS QUITE
A DIFFERENT MATTER.
WE AGREED TO ALLOW ONE
REPRESENTATIVE ON OUR SOIL--
YOUR CAPTAIN.
SIR, OUR CAPTAIN
IS STILL MISSING,
AND I NOW DEMAND
THAT I BE ALLOWED
TO TRANSPORT TO GIDEON
AS WE AGREED.
FORGIVE ME, MR. SPOCK,
BUT I OVERSTEPPED MY AUTHORITY
WHEN I MADE
THAT AGREEMENT.
HOWEVER, YOUR REQUEST
WILL BE TAKEN UP
AT THE NEXT FULL SESSION
OF GIDEON'S COUNCIL.
MR. SCOTT, BEAM
DOWN THE GENTLEMAN
FROM GIDEON.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
I'M SENDING HIM
STRAIGHT TO THE
SAME COORDINATES.
AND JUST WHEN I WAS
BEGINNING TO THINK
YOU MIGHT FIND
A WHOLE NEW CAREER AS
A DIPLOMAT, MR. SPOCK.
DO NOT GIVE UP
HOPE, DOCTOR.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
CONTACT STARFLEET
COMMAND.
DEMAND
AN IMMEDIATE REPLY
TO OUR REQUEST
FOR PERMISSION TO
BEAM DOWN TO GIDEON.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
"ENTERPRISE"
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
Kirk: "ENTERPRISE"
"ENTERPRISE"
TO STARFLEET COMMAND.
CAPTAIN KIRK HERE.
RED PRIORITY.
ISN'T IT
IN WORKING ORDER?
IT SEEMS TO BE.
THEN SOMEONE SHOULD
HAVE HEARD YOU.
CAPTAIN KIRK HERE.
PLEASE ANSWER
RED PRIORITY.
WELL, IF SOMEONE
IS LISTENING,
THEY'RE NOT ANSWERING.
WHY SHOULD THEY
DO THAT?
THEY WOULDN'T.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
TOOK THE SHIP
OUT OF WARP SPEED.
OUT OF WHAT?
SPACE TERMINOLOGY.
WE'RE NO LONGER
MOVING FASTER THAN
THE SPEED OF LIGHT.
I'VE TRIMMED DOWN
TO SUB LIGHT SPEED
UNTIL WE FIND OUT
WHERE WE ARE.
IT FEELS THE SAME.
OF COURSE IT DOES--
MAYBE IT IS
THE SAME.
WELL? HAS THE SHIP
SLOWED DOWN?
IF YOU CAN BELIEVE
THAT, WE HAVE.
OH, PLEASE! DON'T
TELL ME THE SKY IS
OUT OF ORDER NOW.
SO QUIET,
SO PEACEFUL.
IT ISN'T REALLY,
YOU KNOW.
AND IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
YES. YES, IT IS.
VERY,
VERY BEAUTIFUL.
AND WE'RE ALONE.
CAN YOU MAKE IT LAST
A LONG, LONG TIME?
HOW LONG WOULD YOU
LIKE IT TO LAST?
FOREVER.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
POWER--
THAT'S NO PROBLEM.
IT REGENERATES.
AND FOOD--
WE HAVE ENOUGH
TO FEED A CREW
OF 430 FOR 5 YEARS.
SO THAT SHOULD
LAST US--
FOREVER.
ALL MY LIFE,
I'VE DREAMED
OF BEING ALONE.
MOST PEOPLE ARE AFRAID
WHERE I COME FROM,
PEOPLE DREAM OF IT.
WHY? WHY ARE THE PEOPLE
OF GIDEON LIKE THAT?
GIDEON?
I TOLD YOU I DON'T
KNOW WHERE I COME FROM,
WHAT MY PLANET IS.
IT MIGHT BE GIDEON.
DOES IT MATTER
SO MUCH?
YES. IT MIGHT HELP ME
PINPOINT OUR LOCATION.
AND THEN YOU MIGHT
FIND YOUR CREW.
BEING HERE WITH YOU,
I FORGOT
THERE MUST BE OTHERS.
I ENVY YOU
YOUR SENSE OF LOYALTY.
I WANT TO EASE
YOUR FEELING OF DREAD,
YOUR FEAR THAT
ALL YOUR CREW
NO LONGER EXISTS.
I'VE GOT TO
CONTACT WHOEVER IS
MANIPULATING US.
THERE MUST BE A WAY.
ODONA--
ODONA, CAN YOU...
REMEMBER WHY
YOUR PEOPLE DREAM
OF BEING ALONE?
BECAUSE THEY
NEVER CAN BE.
WHY?
WHAT MAKES IT
SO IMPOSSIBLE TO BE ALONE?
BECAUSE THERE ARE
SO MANY OF US.
SO MANY.
THERE IS NO PLACE,
NO STREET,
NO HOUSE, NO GARDEN,
NO BEACH,
NO MOUNTAIN
THAT IS NOT FILLED
WITH PEOPLE.
EACH ONE OF US
WOULD KILL
IN ORDER TO FIND A PLACE
ALONE TO HIMSELF.
THEY WOULD WILLINGLY
DIE FOR IT...
IF THEY COULD.
WHO SENT YOU HERE?
NO ONE COMMANDS
ODONA.
I WAS NOT SENT HERE.
HAVE YOU COME TO KILL?
ODONA, HAVE YOU
COME TO DIE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T CARE.
I ONLY KNOW
I'M HERE.
I'M HAPPY.
NOW ALL I HAVE TO DO
IS FIND A MEDICAL KIT,
AND I CAN COMPLETELY
CURE THIS.
CURE?
YES. THE IRRITATION
WILL BE GONE.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IF YOU DO NOT FIND ONE?
WILL YOU BECOME
SICK AND DIE?
HA HA! NO.
OVER SOMETHING
AS SIMPLE AS THIS?
NO. IT'LL CURE
ITSELF EVENTUALLY, BUT..
DO YOU KNOW, I--
I DON'T EVEN REMEMBER
HOW THIS HAPPENED?
[CHUCKLES]
[LOW-PITCHED THUMPING]
DO YOU HEAR THAT?
YES.
IT SOUNDS LIKE
AN ENGINE.
NO. THE SHIP'S ENGINES
DON'T MAKE THAT KIND
OF SOUND.
BUT THERE IS
SOMETHING WRONG
WITH THE EQUIPMENT.
COULD THAT BE IT?
I KNOW EVERY SOUND
THAT THIS SHIP MIGHT MAKE.
THAT'S COMING
FROM OUTSIDE.
A STORM MIGHT--
A STORM MIGHT,
BUT YOU WOULDN'T
BE ABLE TO HEAR IT.
COME ON.
THIS IS
A VIEWING PORT.
WE'LL BE ABLE
TO SEE OUTSIDE.
IF THERE'S A STORM,
WE'LL BE ABLE TO SEE IT.
IF IT WORKS.
PEOPLE.
THE FACES OF PEOPLE!
AND THEN STARS.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHAT'S OUT THERE?
THE SOUND IS GONE.
IT WAS LIKE
THE HEARTBEAT
OF ALL THOSE PEOPLE,
AND THOUSANDS
UPON THOUSANDS MORE,
PRESSING AGAINST
THE SHIP.
BUT YOU SAID WE WERE
MOVING THROUGH SPACE.
YES, I SAID THAT.
THEN THE PEOPLE
CAN'T BE OUT THERE.
YES, THEY CAN.
PLEASE DON'T
FRIGHTEN ME.
IT COULD
BE A MIRAGE.
THEY COULD EXIST
IN OUR MINDS.
YOU MEAN THAT
WE'RE GOING MAD.
OR SOME POWER IS
CREATING THE ILLUSION
IN OUR MINDS
THAT WE ARE SOMEWHERE
NEAR YOUR PLANET.
BUT WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW!
I THINK I HAVE
AN IDEA.
SO THAT WE WON'T KEEP
TRYING TO FIND OUT
WHERE WE ARE,
THAT WE'LL BE CONTENT
TO STAY HERE.
BE CONTENT!
BE CONTENT?
NOT UNTIL I FIND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY CREW.
ARE THEY DEAD?
I DON'T KNOW!
DID YOU KILL THEM
SO YOU COULD HAVE
THE SHIP TO YOURSELF?
CAPTAIN--
CAPTAIN, SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING TO ME.
I NEVER FELT
LIKE THIS BEFORE.
I'VE NEVER FELT
LIKE THIS BEFORE EITHER.
IS THIS THE WAY
ONE LOOKS
WHEN ONE
IS DEVELOPING
A SICKNESS?
THERE'S NO SICKNESS
ON YOUR PLANET, REMEMBER?
NOW THERE WILL BE.
THERE WILL
BE SICKNESS.
THERE WILL BE DEATH.
HODIN!
YES, CAPTAIN KIRK.
OUR EXPERIMENT HAS PASSED
THE FIRST STAGE.
LET ME IN THERE.
I CAN HELP HER.
WE HAVE NO NEED
OF ANY OF YOUR MEDICINES.
BUT SHE'S ILL!
AND WE ARE GRATEFUL
TO YOU FOR HER ILLNESS.
YOU HAVE DONE WELL,
MY DAUGHTER.
GUARD THE CAPTAIN WELL.
WE SHALL NEED HIM
FOR A LONG TIME.
Man: I SYMPATHIZE
DEEPLY,
BUT STARFLEET
CANNOT OVERRIDE
FEDERATION DIRECTIVES
IN THIS MATTER.
ADMIRAL, THE CREW
WILL NOT UNDERSTAND IT.
HAS YOUR CREW
SUDDENLY BECOME
INTERESTED
IN PROVOKING A WAR?
THAT IS NOT
STARFLEET'S MISSION.
WE WISH ONLY TO SAVE
THE LIFE OF THE CAPTAIN.
YOU HAVE NOT
PROVED YOUR CASE
TO THE FEDERATION--
OR TO STARFLEET,
FOR THAT MATTER.
I AM POSITIVE
THAT I CAN DO SO
TO YOUR SATISFACTION,
ADMIRAL.
I HAVE BEEN CONVINCED
SINCE MY FIRST EXCHANGE
WITH THE AMBASSADOR
THAT THE CAPTAIN HAS
BEEN TAKEN PRISONER.
GRANTED AS FACT,
MR. SPOCK.
I NOW KNOW
WHERE THE CAPTAIN
IS BEING HELD,
IF HE IS BEING HELD
AT THE SAME PLACE
TO WHICH WE
TRANSPORTED HIM.
THEY WOULD NOT DARE
HARM HIM IN THE GIDEON
COUNCIL CHAMBER.
SIR, THE CAPTAIN
IS NOT BEING HELD IN
THE GIDEON COUNCIL CHAMBER.
HE IS BEING HELD
NEARBY.
YOU HAVE NOW
ANSWERED WHAT
AND WHERE.
I'M WAITING FOR
YOUR EXPLANATION
OF WHY.
SINCE THE PLANET
IS SHIELDED
FROM OUR SENSORS,
WE CANNOT ESTABLISH THAT
WITHOUT ON-THE-SPOT
INVESTIGATION.
DO YOU HAVE EVIDENCE
THE CAPTAIN'S LIFE
IS THREATENED?
PERMISSION DENIED.
ADMIRAL, I WISH
TO STATE FOR THE RECORD
THAT YOUR DECISION
IS COMPLETELY ARBITRARY.
SO NOTED.
WILL IT LAST LONG?
THAT DEPENDS
ON THE STRENGTH
OF THE ONE INFECTED.
YOU HAVE
GREAT STRENGTH.
HOW WILL YOU KNOW
WHEN I AM TO DIE?
YOUR BODY TEMPERATURE
WILL BE VERY GREAT.
YOU WILL SEE US,
BUT YOU WILL NOT
KNOW WHO WE ARE.
I MUST SEE HIM
BEFORE THEN, FATHER.
LIE STILL.
[GASPING]
DO YOU FEEL GREAT PAIN?
YES.
IN MY ARMS
AND THIGHS.
WHAT IS IT LIKE
TO FEEL PAIN?
IT IS LIKE...
LIKE WHEN YOU SEE
THE PEOPLE HAVE NO
HOPE FOR HAPPINESS,
FATHER.
YOU FEEL
GREAT DESPAIR,
AND YOUR HEART
IS HEAVY
BECAUSE YOU KNOW
YOU CAN DO NOTHING.
PAIN IS LIKE THAT.
YOUR COURAGE
GIVES ME GREAT PRIDE.
LET ME SEE HER.
NOT YET.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT SHE MAY HAVE.
BUT WE DO. SHE HAS
VEGAN CHORIOMENINGITIS.
THAT'S VERY RARE
AND ALWAYS FATAL
IF NOT TREATED
WITHIN 24 HOURS.
I KNOW. IT ALMOST
KILLED ME.
YES. OUR PRIME MINISTER
LEARNED ABOUT YOU DURING
OUR NEGOTIATIONS.
THAT'S WHY WE
BROUGHT YOU HERE.
YOUR BLOOD PROVIDED
THE MICROORGANISMS
WHICH INFECTED HER.
THAT'S HOW MY ARM
GOT HURT.
YES. AS ODONA TOLD YOU,
WE HAVE NO NEED FOR
MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS HERE.
OUR APOLOGIES.
WE WERE UNFORGIVABLY
AWKWARD TO HAVE HURT YOU.
YOU'RE MAD.
NO. WE ARE DESPERATE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW STARFLEET CAN
DENY US PERMISSION
TO BEAM DOWN TO SEARCH
FOR THE CAPTAIN.
THEY DID NOT
ASK FOR OUR
UNDERSTANDING, DOCTOR.
I DON'T SEE HOW
THEY EXPECT US
TO SIT HERE
AND WAIT
FOR THE CAPTAIN
TO REAPPEAR.
UNFORTUNATELY, I MUST
VIOLATE A DIRECT ORDER
FROM STARFLEET.
THAT'S THE BEST
POSSIBLE DECISION YOU
COULD MAKE, SPOCK.
I'M WITH YOU.
I DO NOT MAKE IT
LIGHTLY, DOCTOR.
HOWEVER, COMMAND KNOWS
THAT AMBASSADOR HODIN
HAS NOT BEEN TOTALLY
HONEST WITH US.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
REPEAT ORIGINAL
GIDEON COORDINATES
FOR BEAM-DOWN.
875.020.079.
MR. SCOTT, COORDINATES
GIVEN YOU?
875.020.709.
THE COORDINATES
DON'T MATCH.
PRECISELY. I SHALL
BEAM DOWN AT ONCE.
MR. SCOTT,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
I'LL PICK UP
MY MEDICAL TRICORDER
AND MEET YOU
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
NEGATIVE, DOCTOR.
I CANNOT ACCEPT
THE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR ORDERING
A FELLOW OFFICER
TO VIOLATE
A STARFLEET DIRECTIVE.
I CAN MAKE SUCH A DECISION
ONLY FOR MYSELF.
I'M NOT
ASKING YOU TO MAKE
THE DECISION FOR ME.
THE SITUATION FORCES ME
TO DO SO, DOCTOR.
IN THAT CASE, IT'S
THE WORST POSSIBLE DECISION
YOU CAN MAKE, SPOCK.
THIS WILL NOT
TAKE LONG.
ISN'T THAT JUST ABOUT
WHAT CAPTAIN KIRK SAID
BEFORE HE LEFT?
[TRICORDER HUMMING]
[HUMMING ENDS]
CAPTAIN KIRK,
SPOCK HERE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
[TRICORDER HUMMING]
YOUR REPORT TO
THE FEDERATION WAS
A TISSUE OF LIES!
YOU DESCRIBED
ENVIRONMENTAL,
PHYSICAL,
CULTURAL CONDITIONS
THAT WOULD MAKE
GIDEON A PARADISE.
Hodin:
AND SO IT WAS.
A LONG, LONG TIME AGO,
WHAT WE DESCRIBED WAS TRUE.
THE ATMOSPHERE ON GIDEON
HAS ALWAYS BEEN GERMFREE,
AND THE PEOPLE FLOURISHED
IN THEIR PHYSICAL
AND SPIRITUAL PERFECTION.
EVENTUALLY, EVEN
THE LIFE SPAN INCREASED.
DEATH BECAME
ALMOST UNKNOWN TO US.
IT OCCURRED ONLY WHEN
THE BODY COULD NO LONGER
REGENERATE ITSELF,
AND THAT HAPPENS NOW
ONLY TO THE VERY OLD.
THOSE ARE CONDITIONS
MOST PEOPLE WOULD ENVY.
BUT GIDEON DID NOT
FIND IT ENVIABLE.
THE BIRTHRATE
CONTINUED TO RISE,
AND THE POPULATION GREW
UNTIL NOW GIDEON IS
ENCASED IN A LIVING MASS
WHO CAN FIND NO REST,
NO PEACE, NO JOY.
THEN WHY HAVEN'T YOU
INTRODUCED ANY OF
THE NEW TECHNIQUES
TO STERILIZE MEN
AND WOMEN?
EVERY ORGAN RENEWS ITSELF.
IT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE.
THEN LET
YOUR PEOPLE LEARN
ABOUT THE DEVICES
TO SAFELY PREVENT
CONCEPTION.
THE FEDERATION
WILL PROVIDE
ANYTHING YOU NEED.
BUT, YOU SEE,
THE PEOPLE OF GIDEON
HAVE ALWAYS BELIEVED
THAT LIFE IS SACRED,
THAT THE LOVE OF LIFE
IS THE GREATEST GIFT.
THAT IS THE ONE
UNSHAKABLE TRUTH OF GIDEON,
AND THIS OVERWHELMING LOVE
OF LIFE HAS DEVELOPED
OUR REGENERATIVE CAPACITY
AND OUR GREAT LONGEVITY.
AND THE GREAT MISERY
WHICH YOU NOW FACE.
THAT IS BITTERLY TRUE,
CAPTAIN.
NEVERTHELESS, WE CANNOT
DENY THE TRUTH WHICH
SHAPED OUR EVOLUTION.
WE ARE INCAPABLE OF
DESTROYING OR INTERFERING
WITH THE CREATION
OF THAT WHICH WE LOVE
SO DEEPLY--
LIFE, IN EVERY FORM, FROM FETUS
TO DEVELOPED BEING.
IT IS AGAINST OUR TRADITION,
AGAINST OUR VERY NATURE.
WE SIMPLY COULD NOT DO IT.
YET YOU CAN KILL
A YOUNG GIRL.
WE'RE TRYING TO READJUST
THE LIFE CYCLE
OF AN ENTIRE
CIVILIZATION!
YOU'RE KILLING
YOUR OWN DAUGHTER!
HOW CAN YOU DO THAT?
MY DAUGHTER HOPED
TO MAKE YOU FEEL
THE AGONY OF GIDEON,
BUT IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE.
NO STRANGER
COULD REALIZE
THE HORROR THAT LIFE
CAN BE HERE.
I WILL NOT BEG
FOR YOUR UNDERSTANDING
OF MY PERSONAL GRIEF,
NOR WILL I PARADE
IT FOR YOU TO GAIN
YOUR COOPERATION.
MY LOVE FOR MY DAUGHTER
IS TOO DEEP FOR DISPLAY.
MY PRIDE IN HER
RUNS EVEN DEEPER.
MY DAUGHTER FREELY CHOSE
TO DO WHAT SHE IS DOING,
AS THE PEOPLE OF GIDEON
ARE FREE TO CHOOSE.
THE VIRUS YOU NEED
IS VERY RARE.
WHO WILL PROVIDE IT?
YOU WILL STAY.
YOUR BLOOD
WILL PROVIDE IT.
NO, SIR. NOT ME.
YOU HAVE MANY METHODS
AVAILABLE TO YOU.
I HAVE MENTIONED
ONLY A FEW.
I DO NOT OFFER MY LIFE
FOR THIS PURPOSE.
I HAVE MANY PLANS,
AND I HAVE HOPES,
OTHER THAN DEATH
FOR ODONA.
MY DAUGHTER PLEADED
WITH YOU TO STAY.
WHAT WAS SAID AND WHAT
HAPPENED BETWEEN US
WAS FOR US ALONE.
SHE HOPED
YOU WOULD LOVE HER
AND WISH TO STAY.
SO THAT WAS YOUR PLAN?
THAT I WOULD FALL
SO UNDER HER SPELL
THAT I
WOULD GIVE UP
MY FREEDOM
AND BECOME
A WILLING SACRIFICE.
STAY WITH US.
WE'RE DESPERATE.
[BEEP BEEP]
ODONA'S FEVER
IS RISING.
SHE'S CALLING THE NAME
OF JAMES KIRK.
YOU SEE, YOU CANNOT
LEAVE US NOW.
GO TO HER.
AN EXACT DUPLICATE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
BUT COMPLETELY
INOPERATIVE.
[COMMUNICATOR SIGNAL]
SPOCK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SCOTT HERE,
MR. SPOCK.
I AM SPEAKING
TO YOU FROM THE BRIDGE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
YOU'RE WHERE?
Spock: ON THE BRIDGE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
MR. SCOTT.
THOSE WERE THE COORDINATES
YOU INSISTED ON.
AND THEY WERE CORRECT.
I AM ON BOARD
AN EXACT DUPLICATE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
OF THE "ENTERPRISE"?
IS IT IN ORBIT,
MR. SPOCK?
IN ORBIT, DOCTOR?
IN A MANNER OF SPEAKING.
GIDEON IS IN ORBIT,
AND THE SHIP IS ON GIDEON.
WELL, THAT'S
A BEGINNING,
BUT WHAT ABOUT
THE CAPTAIN?
I'M SURE
HE'S ON BOARD SOMEWHERE.
I'M PICKING UP
LIFE READINGS.
SPOCK OUT.
Spock, voice-over:
SHIP'S LOG, STARDATE 5423.8.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
REPORTING.
OBVIOUSLY, THE GIDEONS
HAVE TRANSPORTED CAPTAIN KIRK
ONTO THIS REPLICA
OF THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO SO CONFUSE HIS MIND
AS TO MAKE HIM SUSCEPTIBLE
TO SOME EXTRAORDINARY
EXPERIMENT.
IT IS MY INTENTION TO LOCATE
THE CAPTAIN AND WARN HIM
BEFORE THE EXPERIMENT
REACHES ITS CONCLUSION,
WHICH LOGIC INDICATES
MEANS THE END OF
THE CAPTAIN'S LIFE
AS HE KNOWS IT.
[GROANING]
IF YOU DON'T ALLOW ME
TO BRING DR. McCOY
DOWN HERE,
IT'LL SOON BE TOO LATE
TO DO ANYTHING FOR HER.
WE HAVE TOLD YOU.
IT IS HER WISH
AND MINE THAT THERE
BE NO INTERFERENCE
WITH THE NATURAL
PROGRESS OF THE VIRUS.
HER DEATH
IS UNNECESSARY.
EVEN IF SHE LIVES,
HER BLOOD WILL PROVIDE
THE SAME SERUM YOU NEED
AS MINE WOULD.
NO. HER DEATH
AT SO YOUNG AN AGE
WILL LET THE PEOPLE
KNOW FOR CERTAIN
THAT OUR LIFE CYCLE
CAN BE CHANGED.
IT IS THE SYMBOL
THAT WILL BRING FORTH
THE DEDICATED
YOUNG VOLUNTEERS.
THE SERUM
IN THEIR NEW BLOOD
WILL CHANGE GIDEON,
AND IT WILL ONCE MORE BE
THE PARADISE IT WAS.
[ODONA GROANING]
[GASPING]
I'M GLAD
THAT YOU ARE HERE.
IS THE TIME SHORT?
VERY SHORT.
AND I ASKED YOU
TO MAKE OUR JOURNEY
LAST FOREVER.
OH! IT BEGAN HERE.
AND IT CAN CONTINUE.
IF ONLY YOU'LL ALLOW ME,
I CAN CURE YOU.
I AM NOT AFRAID
OF WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
IT IS
JUST THAT NOW...
I WISH WITH
ALL MY HEART TO STAY
WITH YOU FOREVER.
OHH...
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
CAPTAIN,
YOU'RE LOOKING WELL.
EVIDENTLY, STARFLEET'S
ANALYSIS WAS CORRECT.
MR. SPOCK,
WE HAVE A PATIENT
FOR DR. McCOY.
HAVE SCOTTY
BEAM US UP.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
SPOCK TO "ENTERPRISE."
SCOTT HERE.
THREE TO BEAM UP,
MR. SCOTT.
SAME COORDINATES?
NEGATIVE. LOCK IN
ON MY COMMUNICATOR SIGNAL.
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
PLEASE DO NOT INTERFERE.
I ALREADY HAVE
ONE SERIOUS PROBLEM
TO RESOLVE
WITH UPPER ECHELONS.
WELL, THAT WAS CLOSE,
BUT YOU MADE IT.
I AM CURED?
RIGHT. JUST LIKE
THE CAPTAIN.
INSTEAD OF SMILING
AT ME, YOU SHOULD BE
SHOUTING IN ANGER.
WHY? BECAUSE
YOU'RE WELL AGAIN?
NO. BECAUSE
I PRETENDED TO BE--
HOW CAN YOU BEAR
TO LOOK AT ME
AFTER THE WAY
I DECEIVED YOU?
AT LEAST YOU OWE ME
THE PRIVILEGE
OF LETTING ME
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU ARE A GENTLEMAN,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
THANK YOU, MA'AM.
YOU ARE NO LONGER
NEEDED ON GIDEON.
I CAN TAKE
YOUR PLACE THERE.
IS THAT WHAT YOU WANTED?
THAT IS WHAT
I MUST DO.
I AM NEEDED
THERE NOW.
YOU'RE NEEDED
EVERYWHERE, ODONA.
IT IS NOT
LIKE OUR SHIP.
OH, YES, IT IS.
IT'S EXACTLY THE SAME,
ONLY THIS ONE WORKS.
IT GOES TO
MANY OTHER PLANETS?
YES. IT GOES THROUGH
THE WHOLE GALAXY--
WITH ANOTHER DIFFERENCE.
THIS ONE IS CROWDED.
IT SEEMS CROWDED
TO YOU?
IT DOES NOW.
ARE YOU GOING
TO STAY ON THE SHIP?
YES, ODONA.
I HAVE TO.
AS CROWDED
AS MY PLANET IS,
I COULD WISH FOR IT
TO HOLD ONE MORE PERSON.
KIRK TO
TRANSPORTER CONTROL.
ONE TO BEAM DOWN
TO THE PLANET GIDEON.
I WILL MISS YOU,
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.