A GHOST PLANET?
I SUGGEST NO
SUPERNATURAL
EXPLANATION, CAPTAIN.
I MERELY POINT OUT
THAT THE FACTS
DO NOT FIT
ANY KNOWN CATEGORIES
OF PLANETS.
LET'S TAKE THE FACTS
ONE BY ONE.
THAT SHOULD EXPLAIN
SOMETHING.
UNDOUBTEDLY.
THE AGE OF THIS PLANET
WOULD SEEM TO BE ONLY
A FEW THOUSAND YEARS.
IT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE
FOR VEGETATION TO EVOLVE
IN SO SHORT A PERIOD.
ITS SIZE IS
APPROXIMATELY THAT
OF EARTH'S MOON.
BUT ITS MASS
AND ITS ATMOSPHERE
ARE SIMILAR TO EARTH.
THAT WOULD BE
DIFFICULT TO EXPLAIN.
IT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE,
CAPTAIN.
AN ATMOSPHERE COULD NOT
EVOLVE IN SO SHORT
A PERIOD OF TIME.
AND YET IT HAS.
EVIDENTLY.
BUT THE INCONSISTENCIES
ARE SO COMPOUNDED
AS TO PRESENT
A SEEMINGLY IMPOSSIBLE
PHENOMENON.
BUT A FASCINATING ONE,
MR. SPOCK.
PRECISELY, CAPTAIN.
IT WOULD BEAR
CLOSER INVESTIGATION,
IT WOULD SEEM,
IF WE'RE TO PROVIDE
STARFLEET WITH
AN ACCURATE REPORT.
LIEUTENANT,
SEND DR. McCOY
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
FOR SURVEY PARTY.
WE'LL ALSO NEED SENIOR
GEOLOGIST D'AMATO.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
FEED BEAMDOWN
COORDINATES TO
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
MR. SULU,
YOU'LL ACCOMPANY ME.
MR. SPOCK,
YOU HAVE THE CON.
LIEUTENANT RADHA,
REPORT TO THE BRIDGE
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS EXPEDITION SHOULD
BE A GEOLOGIST'S DREAM,
MR. D'AMATO.
WELL, THE OPPORTUNITY
TO EXPLORE SO YOUNG
A PLANET
IS AN INCREDIBLE BIT
OF LUCK, CAPTAIN.
YES. IF MR. SPOCK
IS CORRECT, YOU'LL
HAVE A REPORT
TO STARTLE
THE FIFTH INTERSTELLAR
GEOPHYSICAL CONFERENCE.
WHY? WHAT IS IT, JIM?
A PLANET EVEN SPOCK
CAN'T EXPLAIN.
PREPARE TO TRANSPORT.
ENERGIZE.
WAIT! YOU MUST NOT GO!
JIM, DID YOU SEE
WHAT I SAW?
THAT WOMAN ATTACKED
ENSIGN WYATT. KIRK TO--
CAPTAIN. CAPTAIN!
MR. SPOCK!
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
I BELIEVE
NO PERMANENT DAMAGE
WAS DONE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THE OCCIPITAL AREA
OF MY HEAD SEEMS
TO HAVE IMPACTED WITH
THE ARM OF THE CHAIR.
NO, MR. SPOCK. I MEANT
WHAT HAPPENED TO US?
THAT WE HAVE YET
TO ASCERTAIN.
MR. SPOCK.
THE PLANET'S GONE!
WHAT KIND OF
EARTHQUAKES DO THEY
HAVE IN THIS PLACE?
I DON'T KNOW. ANY MORE
LIKE THAT, IT'LL TEAR
THIS PLANET APART.
CAPTAIN?
THIS TREMOR WE FELT,
IF THAT'S WHAT IT WAS--
AND IT'S CERTAINLY
LIKE NO SEISMIC
DISTURBANCE
I'VE EVER FELT BEFORE--
I GOT A READING OF
ALMOST IMMEASURABLE
POWER.
BUT IT'S NOT THERE
ANYMORE.
COULD SEISMIC STRESS
HAVE ACCOUNTED FOR IT?
THE READING I GOT
HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE SEISMIC FORCE.
THAT'S VERY STRANGE.
AND THAT WOMAN?
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
COME IN.
HMM. SHOCK MAY HAVE
DAMAGED IT.
IT'S GONE!
THE ENTERPRISE,
HE'S RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING THERE.
HOW COULD IT JUST BE GONE?
WHAT THE DEVIL DOES THAT
MEAN, JIM?
FOR ONE THING...
IT MEANS
WE'RE STRANDED.
SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS FIVE-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
THE ENTERPRISE
MUST HAVE BLOWN UP.
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN
THE HIGH RADIATION
READINGS,
WOULDN'T IT,
CAPTAIN, IF THE
MATTER/ANTIMATTER--
SHALL WE STOP GUESSING,
MR. SULU, AND TRY AND
ESTABLISH A PATTERN?
I GET NO READINGS
OF HIGH ENERGY
CONCENTRATION.
IF THE ENTERPRISE
HAD BLOWN UP,
IT WOULD HAVE LEFT
A HIGH RESIDUAL
RADIATION.
COULD IT BE
THE ENTERPRISE HIT US,
HIT THE PLANET?
ONCE IN SIBERIA,
THERE WAS A METEOR
SO GREAT
THAT IT FLATTENED
WHOLE FORESTS AND
WAS FELT AS FAR--
MR. SULU, IF I'D
WANTED A RUSSIAN
HISTORY LESSON,
I'D HAVE BROUGHT ALONG
MR. CHEKOV.
THIS IS A MATTER
OF SURVIVAL, GENTLEMEN.
WITHOUT THE ENTERPRISE,
WE NEED FOOD
AND WE NEED WATER
AND WE NEED THEM FAST.
I WANT A DETAILED ANALYSIS
MADE OF THIS PLANET
AND I WANT IT NOW.
AYE, SIR.
YES, SIR.
MR. SULU.
ENGINEERING, NO DAMAGE.
ALL POWER LEVELS NORMAL.
DAMAGE CONTROL
REPORT.
SHIP FUNCTIONING
NORMALLY.
MANY BUMPS
AND BRUISES.
ONE CASUALTY,
MR. SPOCK.
THE TRANSPORTER
OFFICER.
HE'S DEAD.
DEAD?
SPOCK TO SICK BAY.
SICK BAY.
DOCTOR M'BENGA.
REPORT ON THE DEATH
OF THE TRANSPORTER
OFFICER.
WELL, WE'RE NOT SURE.
DR. SANCHEZ
IS CONDUCTING
AN AUTOPSY RIGHT NOW.
HMM.
GIVE ME A FULL REPORT
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, PLEASE.
SPOCK OUT.
MR. SCOTT...
HAVE THE TRANSPORTER
CHECKED FOR POSSIBLE
MALFUNCTION.
AYE, SIR.
NO DEBRIS
OF ANY KIND, SIR.
I'VE MADE
TWO FULL SCANS.
IF THE PLANET HAD
BROKEN UP, THERE'D
BE SOME SIGN.
BUT WHAT BOTHERS ME
IS THE STARS,
MR. SPOCK.
THE STARS.
YES, SIR.
THEY'RE WRONG.
WRONG?
YES, MR. SPOCK.
LOOK.
NOW HERE'S A REPLAY
OF THE STAR PATTERN
JUST BEFORE
THE EXPLOSION.
HMM.
A POSITIONAL CHANGE.
IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
BUT SOMEHOW I'D SAY
THAT IN A FLASH,
WE'VE BEEN KNOCKED
1,000 LIGHT YEARS
AWAY FROM
WHERE WE WERE.
990.7 LIGHT YEARS
TO BE EXACT,
LIEUTENANT.
BUT THAT'S NOT
POSSIBLE.
NOTHING
CAN DO THAT.
MR. SCOTT,
SINCE WE ARE HERE,
YOUR STATEMENT
IS NOT ONLY ILLOGICAL
BUT ALSO UNWORTHY
OF REFUTATION.
IT IS ALSO ILLOGICAL
TO ASSUME
THAT ANY EXPLOSION,
EVEN THAT OF A SMALL STAR
GOING SUPERNOVA,
COULD HAVE HURLED US
A DISTANCE OF 990.7
LIGHT YEARS.
BUT THE POINT IS
IT SHOULDN'T HAVE
HURLED US ANYWHERE!
WHY, IT SHOULD HAVE
DESTROYED US IMMEDIATELY,
VAPORIZED US!
THAT IS CORRECT,
MR. SCOTT,
BY ALL THE LAWS
THAT WE KNOW.
THERE WAS NO PERIOD
OF UNCONSCIOUSNESS.
OUR SHIP'S CHRONOMETERS
REGISTERED A MATTER
OF ONLY A FEW SECONDS.
THEREFORE, WE WERE
DISPLACED THROUGH SPACE
IN SOME MANNER
WHICH I AM UNABLE
TO FATHOM.
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING
IS THAT THE PLANET
DIDN'T BLOW UP
AND THE CAPTAIN
AND THE OTHERS,
THEY'RE STILL ALIVE!
PLEASE, MR. SCOTT,
RESTRAIN YOUR LEAPS
OF ILLOGIC.
I HAVE SAID NOTHING.
I WAS MERELY SPECULATING.
[BEEP]
SICK BAY
TO MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
YOU ASKED FOR
AN AUTOPSY REPORT.
IT'S ONLY PRELIMINARY,
BUT THE CAUSE OF DEATH
SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN
CELLULAR DISRUPTION.
EXPLAIN.
WELL, IT'S AS THOUGH
EVERY CELL IN THE BODY
HAD BEEN INDIVIDUALLY
BLASTED FROM INSIDE.
WOULD ANY KNOWN
DISEASE ORGANISM
DO THAT?
DR. SANCHEZ HAS RULED
THAT POSSIBILITY OUT, SIR.
PLEASE KEEP ME
FULLY ADVISED.
SPOCK OUT.
HE WAS IN
THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
SOMEONE MAY HAVE ENTERED
AFTER CAPTAIN KIRK
AND HIS PARTY LEFT.
MR. SCOTT,
SINCE THE ENTERPRISE
IS OBVIOUSLY FUNCTIONAL,
I SUGGEST WE RETURN
TO OUR STARTING PLACE
AT TOP WARP SPEED.
AYE, SIR.
BUT EVEN AT THAT,
IT'LL TAKE US A
WHILE TO GET THERE.
IN THAT CASE,
MR. SCOTT,
I SUGGEST
WE START AT ONCE.
CAN YOU GIVE ME
WARP 8?
AYE, SIR. AND MAYBE
A WEE BIT MORE.
I'LL SIT ON THE
WARP ENGINES MYSELF
AND NURSE THEM.
THAT POSITION,
MR. SCOTT,
WOULD NOT ONLY BE
UNAVAILING,
BUT ALSO...UNDIGNIFIED.
LIEUTENANT RADHA,
PLOT A COURSE.
ALREADY PLOTTED
AND LAID IN, SIR.
GOOD.
THEN PREPARE TO COME
TO WARP 8.
YOUR REPORT COVERS
ALL VEGETATION?
YES, CAPTAIN.
ALL VEGETATION
IS INEDIBLE,
POISON TO US.
IF THE ENTERPRISE
HAS BEEN DESTROYED,
DO YOU KNOW HOW LONG
WE CAN SURVIVE?
YES.
I DON'T SEE ANY WATER,
BUT THERE MUST BE SOME
TO GROW THE VEGETATION.
A SOURCE OF WATER
WOULD STRETCH
OUR SURVIVAL.
DID YOU SEE
ANY EVIDENCE
OF RAINFALL?
NO, SIR. AND I HAVEN'T
SEEN ANY EVIDENCE
THAT THERE EVER HAS
BEEN ANY RAINFALL.
BUT THERE
IS EARTH-TYPE
VEGETATION.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THE VEGETATION COULD
ABSORB THE WATER
DIRECTLY FROM THE AIR?
YES,
THAT'S POSSIBLE.
THERE'S ALSO
THE POSSIBILITY OF
UNDERGROUND WATER.
YES, SIR.
IT COULD BE.
WELL, SULU'S PICKED UP
AN ORGANISM
THAT'S ALMOST A VIRUS,
LIKE A PLANT PARASITE,
AND IT'S THE NEAREST
BIOLOGICAL FORM OF LIFE
THAT I CAN FIND.
THIS APPARENTLY IS GOING
TO BE OUR HOME FOR
AS LONG AS WE LAST.
I SUGGEST WE FIND OUT
AS MUCH AS WE CAN
ABOUT IT.
WE'LL SPLIT UP.
D'AMATO,
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
UNDERGROUND WATER.
YES, SIR.
SULU, RUN AN ATMOSPHERIC
ANALYSIS.
AYE, SIR.
BONES, SEE IF YOU CAN
FIND OUT ANYTHING
ABOUT THE VEGETATION
AND YOUR PARASITE.
HOW DO THEY GET
THEIR MOISTURE?
IF YOU CAN DISCOVER
HOW THEY SURVIVE,
MAYBE WE CAN.
SULU TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
CAPTAIN, I WAS MAKING
A STANDARD MAGNETIC
SWEEP.
FROM ZERO,
I SUDDENLY GOT A READING
THAT WAS OFF THE SCALE,
THEN A REVERSE
OF POLARITY, AND...
NOW I GET NOTHING.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THIS READING...
LIKE...A DOOR OPENED
AND THEN CLOSED AGAIN.
KIRK OUT.
DO NOT BE AFRAID.
I'M NOT.
GEOLOGICAL DISTURBANCES
DON'T FRIGHTEN ME.
I'VE COME HERE
TO STUDY THEM.
MY SPECIALTY.
I KNOW.
YOU ARE LIEUTENANT
D'AMATO,
SENIOR GEOLOGIST.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
FROM THE SPACE SHIP
ENTERPRISE.
YES, AND WE'RE
STRANDED HERE.
YOU BEEN TALKING
TO MY FRIENDS?
DO NOT BE AFRAID.
OH, I'M NOT AFRAID.
I AM FOR YOU,
LIEUTENANT D'AMATO.
WHY, YOU'RE--
YOU'RE THE WOMAN
ON THE ENTERPRISE.
I AM ONLY FOR
D'AMATO.
WELL, LUCKY D'AMATO.
I WANT TO HAVE
A CONFERENCE
ABOUT SHARING
YOUR FOOD AND WATER.
DO NOT CALL THE OTHERS...
PLEASE.
McCOY TO KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
JIM, I JUST GOT
A LIFE FORM READING
OF TREMENDOUS INTENSITY.
SUDDENLY IT WAS
JUST THERE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
JUST THERE?
JUST THAT.
ALL LEVELS WERE NORMAL,
AND THEN I GET THIS
BIOLOGICAL SURGE OF
LIFE FORM REGISTERING.
NO. NOW IT'S GONE.
AS THOUGH A DOOR
OPENED AND CLOSED.
YES.
WHAT DIRECTION?
WAIT A MINUTE. ZERO...
0-8-3.
HANG ON.
D'AMATO SECTION.
COME IN.
KIRK TO D'AMATO.
COME IN!
BONES, SULU,
D'AMATO DOESN'T ANSWER.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
BONES!
JIM, EVERY CELL
IN HIS BODY'S
BEEN DISRUPTED.
JIM, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
DIGGING A GRAVE.
POOR D'AMATO.
WHAT A TERRIBLE
WAY TO DIE.
THERE ARE
NO GOOD WAYS, SULU.
THAT'S THE SAME
RED ROCK.
MY PHASER DIDN'T
CUT THROUGH IT.
WHATEVER IT IS,
IT HAS A MIGHTY HIGH
MELTING POINT.
8,000 DEGREES
CENTIGRADE.
IT LOOKS LIKE
IGNEOUS ROCK,
BUT INFINITELY
DENSER.
THIS WHOLE PLANET
MUST BE MADE UP
OF THIS SUBSTANCE
COVERED OVER
BY TOPSOIL.
MR. SULU, IT MIGHT
EXPLAIN THIS PLACE
A LITTLE BETTER IF WE KNEW
WHAT THE SUBSTANCE IS.
I KNOW IT WAS
D'AMATO'S FIELD,
BUT SEE WHAT
YOU CAN FIND OUT.
YES, SIR.
WELL, I GUESS
A TOMB OF ROCKS
IS THE BEST
WE CAN PROVIDE
FOR D'AMATO.
YEAH.
IT MIGHT BE
THE MOST SUITABLE
MEMORIAL AT THAT.
I WONDER
WHAT KILLED HIM.
I DON'T KNOW...
BUT SOMETHING OR...
SOMEONE...DID.
WE'RE HOLDING
WARP 8.4, SIR.
IF WE CAN MAINTAIN IT,
OUR ESTIMATED
TIME OF ARRIVAL
IS 11 AND 1/2
SOLAR HOURS.
11.337 HOURS,
LIEUTENANT.
I WISH YOU WOULD BE
MORE PRECISE.
SCOTT TO BRIDGE.
[BEEP]
SPOCK HERE.
MR. SPOCK, THE SHIP
FEELS WRONG.
"FEELS," MR. SCOTT?
I KNOW IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
INSTRUMENTATION
READS CORRECT, BUT
THE FEEL IS WRONG!
IT'S SOMETHING
I CAN'T QUITE PUT
INTO WORDS.
THAT IS OBVIOUS,
MR. SCOTT.
I SUGGEST YOU AVOID
EMOTIONALISM
AND SIMPLY KEEP
YOUR INSTRUMENTS
CORRECT.
SPOCK OUT.
IT LOOKS
SO LONELY THERE.
IT WOULD BE WORSE
IF HE HAD COMPANY.
DOCTOR,
HOW CAN YOU
JOKE ABOUT IT?
I'M NOT JOKING.
UNTIL WE KNOW
WHAT KILLED HIM,
NONE OF US IS SAFE.
WE'VE GOT
TO FIGURE THIS OUT
AND DEVISE
A DEFENSE AGAINST IT.
IS IT POSSIBLE
THE ROCKS HAVE LIFE?
YOU REMEMBER
ON JANUS SIX, THE
SILICON CREATURES--
BUT OUR INSTRUMENTS
RECORDED THAT.
THEY WERE LIFE FORMS.
THEY REGISTERED
AS LIFE FORMS.
UNLESS WE'RE DEALING
WITH BEINGS--
INTELLIGENT BEINGS--
WHO CAN SHIELD THEMSELVES.
BEINGS
INTELLIGENT ENOUGH
TO HAVE DESTROYED
THE ENTERPRISE?
THAT'S THE PROBLEM, SULU.
WE HAVE ONLY QUESTIONS....
NO ANSWERS.
WATKINS.
CHECK
THE BYPASS VALVE
ON THE
MATTER/ANTIMATTER
REACTION CHAMBER.
MAKE SURE IT'S NOT
OVERHEATING.
BUT, MR. SCOTT,
THE BOARD SHOWS
CORRECT.
I DIDN'T ASK YOU
TO CHECK THE BOARD,
LAD.
YES, SIR.
WHO ARE YOU?
MY NAME
IS NOT IMPORTANT.
YOURS IS WATKINS,
JOHN B.
ENGINEER GRADE 4.
YOU KNOW
ALL ABOUT ME.
I'VE NEVER
SEEN YOU BEFORE.
SHOW ME THIS UNIT.
I WISH TO LEARN.
WELL, THIS IS
THE MATTER/ANTIMATTER
INTEGRATOR CONTROL.
THAT'S
THE CUTOFF SWITCH.
NOT CORRECT.
THAT IS THE EMERGENCY
OVERLOAD BYPASS,
WHICH ENGAGES
ALMOST INSTANTANEOUSLY.
A WISE PRECAUTION,
CONSIDERING IT TAKES
THE ANTIMATTER
LONGER TO EXPLODE
ONCE THE MAGNETIC
FLOW FAILS.
I AM FOR YOU,
MR. WATKINS.
MR. SCOTT,
THERE'S A STRANGE WOMAN
WHO KNOWS THE ENTIRE PLAN
OF THE ENTERPRISE.
AAH!
OH, YA POOR LAD.
SCOTT TO BRIDGE.
SPOCK HERE.
MY ASSISTANT WATKINS
IS DEAD.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT HE DIED OF,
MR. SCOTT?
I DIDN'T SEE IT
HAPPEN,
BUT HIS LAST WORDS
WERE A WARNING CRY
ABOUT SOME STRANGE
WOMAN.
SECURITY ALERT,
ALL DECKS.
FEMALE INTRUDER.
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
SECURITY ALERT.
ALL DECKS.
CONCLUSIONS.
THE BASIC SUBSTANCE
OF THIS PLANET
IS AN ALLOY
OF DIBURNIUM-OSMIUM.
IT COULDN'T HAVE
EVOLVED NATURALLY.
CAPTAIN, IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
IN FACT, NOTHING
ABOUT THIS PLANET
MAKES SENSE.
EXCEPT FOR
A MOMENTARY
FLUCTUATION
ON YOUR
INSTRUMENTS,
THIS PLANET
HAS NO MAGNETIC
FIELD.
THE APPARENT
AGE OF THESE
ROCKS
IS ONLY A FEW
THOUSAND YEARS.
NO KNOWN PROCESS
COULD EVOLVE
THE PLANT LIFE
THEY HAVE HERE
IN THAT SHORT
SPACE OF TIME.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THIS MIGHT BE
AN ARTIFICIAL PLANET?
BUT, CAPTAIN, WHERE ARE
THE PEOPLE WHO MADE IT?
WHY CAN'T WE SEE THEM?
THE PLANET
MIGHT BE HOLLOW.
THEY MIGHT BE
SHIELDING
THEMSELVES
FROM OUR
SENSOR PROBES.
IT'S DARK.
LET'S GET SOME REST.
TOMORROW WE'LL HAVE
TO FIND SOME FOOD
AND SOME WATER,
OR IT'S GOING
TO BE A VERY
UNPLEASANT STAY.
WHILE IT LASTS.
I'LL TAKE
THE FIRST WATCH, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE D'AMATO'S
TRICORDER.
SET IT FOR
AUTOMATIC DISTRESS.
YOU NEVER CAN TELL.
AYE, SIR.
[BEEPING]
SPOCK TO SICK BAY.
HAVE YOU
COMPLETED THE AUTOPSY
ON WATKINS, DOCTOR?
YES, WE HAVE,
MR. SPOCK.
WAS THE CAUSE
OF HIS DEATH THE SAME
AS THAT WHICH KILLED
THE TRANSPORTER OFFICER?
WELL, THE PATTERN
OF CELLULAR DISRUPTION
WAS THE SAME.
BUT AS TO THE CAUSE,
WELL, YOUR GUESS IS
AS GOOD AS MINE.
MY GUESS, DOCTOR,
WOULD BE VALUELESS.
I SUGGEST WE REFRAIN
FROM GUESSING AND FIND
SOME FACTS.
SPOCK OUT.
THE POWER
OF THIS INTRUDER
TO DISRUPT
EVERY CELL IN A BODY...
COMBINED WITH THE ALMOST
INCONCEIVABLE POWER
REQUIRED TO HURL
THE ENTERPRISE
SUCH A DISTANCE
SPEAK OF
A VERY HIGH CULTURE
AND A VERY GREAT DANGER.
YOU MEAN THAT ONE OF
THE PEOPLE WHO THREW US
1,000 LIGHT YEARS AWAY
FROM THAT PLANET
IS ONBOARD
AND KILLING OUR PEOPLE?
A REASONABLE ASSUMPTION,
MR. SCOTT.
THEN YOU'RE RIGHT,
MR. SPOCK.
WATKINS MUST'VE
BEEN MURDERED.
I SENT HIM IN TO CHECK
THE MATTER/ANTIMATTER
REACTOR.
THERE ARE NO EXPOSED
CIRCUITS THERE.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
ANYTHING HE TOUCHED.
IF THERE ARE MORE
OF THOSE BEINGS
ON THAT PLANET,
THE CAPTAIN
AND THE OTHERS ARE
IN VERY GREAT DANGER.
I AM UNARMED.
WHO ARE YOU?
THAT IS NOT IMPORTANT.
YOU ARE LIEUTENANT SULU?
YOU WERE BORN
ON THE PLANET EARTH.
YOU'RE HELMSMAN
FOR THE ENTERPRISE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THIS?
WHERE DID YOU GET
THIS INFORMATION?
ARE YOU FROM
THIS PLANET?
I AM FROM HERE.
THEN THE PLANET
IS HOLLOW.
WHO KILLED
LIEUTENANT D'AMATO?
ALL RIGHT.
THE CAPTAIN WILL WANT
TO TALK TO YOU.
THAT WAY.
MOVE!
YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
I HAVE COME FOR YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I WANT...TO TOUCH YOU.
YOU WERE ON
THE ENTERPRISE.
KEEP BACK!
STOP
OR I'LL SHOOT!
I DON'T WANT
TO HAVE TO KILL
A WOMAN!
CAPTAIN KIRK!
AAH!
HOLD IT!
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM FOR HIM.
I AM FOR
LIEUTENANT SULU.
DON'T LET HER
TOUCH YOU, CAPTAIN!
THAT'S HOW D'AMATO DIED!
PHASERS WON'T STOP HER!
I AM FOR LIEUTENANT SULU.
PLEASE, I MUST TOUCH HIM.
HOW CAN YOU
DESTROY OTHERS
AND NOT ME?
I DON'T WANT TO DESTROY.
I DON'T WANT TO.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHY ARE YOU TRYING
TO KILL US?
ONLY SULU.
I MEAN YOU NO HARM.
ARE THERE MEN
ON THIS PLANET?
PLEASE,
I MUST TOUCH HIM.
I AM FOR
LIEUTENANT SULU.
NO!
BONES, DID YOU SEE THAT?
MAYBE SPOCK WAS WRONG.
PERHAPS THIS IS
A GHOST PLANET.
WELL, ALL I KNOW IS THAT
SHE ALMOST MADE A GHOST
OUT OF SULU.
HIS SHOULDER,
WHERE SHE TOUCHED IT,
EVERY CELL'S BEEN
DISRUPTED, EXPLODED
FROM WITHIN.
IF SHE'D REALLY
GOTTEN A GOOD GRIP
ON HIM, JIM--
HOW CAN SUCH PEOPLE BE,
CAPTAIN?
SUCH EVIL...
AND SHE'S SO...
SO BEAUTIFUL.
YES, I KNOW.
SECURITY SWEEPS
OF ALL DECKS ARE
NEGATIVE, MR. SPOCK.
NO EVIDENCE OF INTRUDER.
VERY WELL. CANCEL
RED ALERT, BUT MAINTAIN
INCREASED SECURITY.
AYE, SIR. ALL DECKS,
CANCEL RED ALERT.
MAINTAIN
INCREASED SECURITY.
PLEASE UPDATE
OUR SUBSPACE REPORT
TO STARFLEET
TO INCLUDE
SECURITY SEARCH.
RESULTS NEGATIVE.
HOW DID SHE GET OFF
THE SHIP, SIR?
PRESUMABLY
THE SAME WAY SHE GOT ON.
YES, SIR.
MR. SPOCK...
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
OF THE CAPTAIN
AND THE OTHERS
BEING ALIVE?
LIEUTENANT, WE ARE NOT
ENGAGED IN GAMBLING.
WE ARE PROCEEDING
IN THE ONLY LOGICAL WAY
TO RETURN TO THE PLACE
THEY WERE LAST SEEN
AND FACTUALLY ASCERTAIN
WHETHER OR NOT THEY STILL LIVE.
YES, MR. SPOCK.
MR. SPOCK, SPEED IS
INCREASED TO WARP 8.8.
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
SCOTTY HERE.
I SEE IT.
IT'S A POWER SURGE.
I'M WORKING ON IT.
REDUCE SPEED UNTIL I
LOCATE THE TROUBLE.
VERY WELL.
REDUCE SPEED TO WARP 7.
AYE, SIR, WARP 7.
MR. SPOCK...
OUR SPEED
IS INCREASED
TO WARP 8.9
AND STILL CLIMBING.
BRIDGE TO ENGINEERING.
NEGATIVE EFFECT
ON POWER REDUCTION.
SPEED IS STILL INCREASING.
AYE, MR. SPOCK,
AND I FOUND OUT WHY.
THE EMERGENCY
BYPASS CONTROL
OF THE MATTER/
ANTIMATTER
INTEGRATOR IS FUSED.
IT'S COMPLETELY
USELESS.
THE ENGINES
ARE RUNNING WILD.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO GET AT THEM.
WE SHOULD REACH
MAXIMUM OVERLOAD IN
ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
I WOULD CALCULATE
14.87 MINUTES, MR. SCOTT.
THOSE FEW SECONDS
WILL NOT MAKE ANY
DIFFERENCE, MR. SPOCK,
BECAUSE YOU AND I AND
THE REST OF THE CREW
WILL NO LONGER
BE HERE TO BANDY IT
BACK AND FORTH.
THIS THING IS GOING
TO BLOW UP...
AND THERE'S NOTHING
IN THE UNIVERSE
CAN STOP IT.
THERE'S A LAYER
OF NECROTIC TISSUE
A FEW CELLS THICK.
A NORMAL WOUND
WOULD HEAL QUICKLY.
SHE JUST...TOUCHED ME.
HOW COULD IT HAPPEN
SO FAST?
THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
SHE TOUCHED
THE TRANSPORTER CHIEF.
HE COLLAPSED IMMEDIATELY.
SHE APPARENTLY GOT
TO D'AMATO.
WE SAW
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
THE QUESTION IS...
WHY ARE YOU ALIVE?
CAPTAIN, I'M HAPPY
THE WAY IT TURNED OUT.
JIM...
WHAT KIND OF POWER
MUST SHE HAVE?
THE POWER TO TOTALLY DISRUPT
BIOLOGICAL CELL STRUCTURE.
SULU'S ALIVE
BECAUSE I INTERVENED.
BUT THAT RAISES
AN EVEN WORSE QUESTION.
YES.
WHY DIDN'T
SHE KILL YOU?
SHE'S NOT THROUGH YET.
IT'S USELESS.
AND THERE'S NO QUESTION
IT'S DELIBERATE.
SABOTAGE.
AYE, AND A THOROUGH JOB.
THE SYSTEM'S FOOLPROOF.
WHOEVER MURDERED WATKINS
SABOTAGED THIS.
YOU SAID IT WAS FUSED.
HOW?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
WORRIES ME.
WORRIES, MR. SCOTT?
WELL, IT'S FUSED,
ALL RIGHT,
BUT IT WOULD TAKE
ALL THE POWER OF OUR
MAIN PHASER BANKS TO DO IT.
INTERESTING.
I FIND NOTHING INTERESTING
IN THE FACT THAT WE'RE
ABOUT TO BLOW UP.
NO...BUT THE METHOD
IS FASCINATING.
WHATEVER DID THIS
IS STILL ABOARD THIS SHIP.
I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU CANCELED
THE SECURITY ALERT.
A FORCE
THAT COULD HURL US
990.7 LIGHT YEARS AWAY
AND AT THAT DISTANCE
STILL BE ABLE
TO SABOTAGE OUR
MAIN SOURCE OF ENERGY
WILL NOT BE
WAITING AROUND TO BE
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY.
AYE.
AS I RECALL THE PATTERN
OF OUR FUEL FLOW,
THERE IS AN
ACCESS TUBE LEADING
TO THE MATTER/ANTIMATTER
REACTION CHAMBER.
AYE, THERE'S
A SERVICE CRAWLWAY,
BUT IT'S NOT MEANT
TO BE USED WHILE THE
INTEGRATOR OPERATES.
STILL, IT IS THERE,
AND IT MIGHT BE POSSIBLE
TO SHUT OFF THE FLOW
OF FUEL AT THAT POINT.
WHAT WITH?
BARE HANDS?
A MAGNETIC PROBE.
ANY MATTER THAT
COMES IN CONTACT
WITH ANTIMATTER
TRIGGERS THE EXPLOSION.
AND I'M NOT EVEN SURE
A MAN CAN LIVE
IN THE CRAWLWAY
IN THE ENERGY STREAM
OF THE MAGNETIC FIELD
THAT BOTTLES UP
THE ANTIMATTER.
I SHALL TRY.
YOU'LL BE KILLED, MAN.
UNLESS A SOLUTION
IS FOUND QUICKLY,
THAT FATE AWAITS
ALL OF US.
AYE. YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT
TO LOSE?
BUT I'LL DO IT,
MR. SPOCK.
I KNOW
EVERY MILLIMETER
OF THAT SYSTEM.
I'LL DO WHATEVER
HAS TO BE DONE.
VERY WELL, MR. SCOTT.
YOU SPOKE OF THE FEEL
OF THE SHIP BEING WRONG.
AYE. IT WAS
AN EMOTIONAL STATEMENT.
I DON'T EXPECT YOU
TO UNDERSTAND IT.
I NOTE IT, MR. SCOTT,
WITHOUT NECESSARILY
UNDERSTANDING IT.
I PROPOSE TO RUN
AN ANALYSIS THROUGH
THE SHIP'S COMPUTERS,
COMPARING
THE PRESENT CONDITION
OF THE ENTERPRISE
WITH HER IDEAL CONDITION.
MR. SPOCK,
WE DON'T HAVE
TIME FOR THAT.
WE HAVE 12 MINUTES
AND 27 SECONDS.
I SUGGEST YOU DO
WHATEVER YOU CAN IN
THE SERVICE CRAWLWAY,
WHILE I MAKE
THE COMPUTER STUDY.
LIEUTENANT SULU,
DO YOU FEEL STRONG
ENOUGH TO MOVE ABOUT?
I FEEL FINE, CAPTAIN.
IS HE, BONES?
HE'S IN FAIR SHAPE.
ALL RIGHT.
WHATEVER DESTRUCTIVE POWER
THIS WOMAN HAS SEEMS
TO BE AIMED AT ONE
SPECIFIC PERSON
AT ONE SPECIFIC TIME.
IF I'M CORRECT,
WHEN SHE REAPPEARS,
THE OTHER TWO MIGHT
BE ABLE TO PROTECT
THE ONE SHE'S AFTER
BY INTERPOSING
THEIR BODIES.
NO WEAPONS SEEM
TO AFFECT HER.
BUT, CAPTAIN, HOW DOES
SHE KNOW ABOUT US?
DOES SHE READ OUR MINDS?
[HIGH-PITCHED WHINE]
PHASER ON OVERLOAD!
CONTROLS ARE FUSED.
DROP!
APPARENTLY SHE CAN
DESTROY OUR WEAPONS
AS WELL AS DESTROY US.
COME ON. LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT, LADS.
GET THE CRAWLWAY DOOR OPEN.
HAND ME THE TOOLS.
COMMUNICATOR.
ALL RIGHT. HEAD FIRST.
I HOPE MR. SPOCK KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOING.
SCOTT TO BRIDGE.
[SPOCK]
GO AHEAD, MR. SCOTT.
I'VE SEALED OFF
THE AFT END OF THE
SERVICE CRAWLWAY,
AND I'VE POSITIONED
EXPLOSIVE SEPARATOR
CHARGES TO BLAST ME
CLEAR OF THE SHIP
IF I RUPTURE
THE MAGNETIC BOTTLE.
I'M SO CLOSE
TO THE FLOW NOW,
AND IT FEELS
LIKE ANTS CRAWLING
ALL OVER MY BODY.
MR. SCOTT,
I SUGGEST YOU REFRAIN
FROM ANY FURTHER
SUBJECTIVE DESCRIPTIONS.
YOU NOW HAVE 10 MINUTES
AND 19 SECONDS
IN WHICH TO PERFORM
YOUR TASK.
[RADHA]
MR. SPOCK,
WE'RE AT WARP 11.2
AND ACCELERATING.
I HEARD THAT.
THE SHIP'S NOT
STRUCTURED TO TAKE
THAT SPEED
FOR ANY LENGTH OF TIME.
YOU NOW HAVE 10 MINUTES
AND 10 SECONDS.
ALL RIGHT, MR. SPOCK.
I'M STARTING TO OPEN
THE ACCESS PANEL NOW,
ACCESS
TO THE FLOW ITSELF.
IF THE MAGNETIC FLOW
JUMPS,
YOU MUST JETTISON ME.
THE SAFETY CONTROL
WILL NOT HOLD
MORE THAN 2 SECONDS
IF I RUPTURE THE FIELD.
I AM AWARE
OF THESE FACTS.
PLEASE GET ON
WITH THE JOB.
COMPUTER.
WORKING.
ANALYSIS ON
MY COMPARISON
COORDINATES.
UNABLE TO COMPLY.
COMPARISON COORDINATES
TOO COMPLEX FOR
IMMEDIATE READOUT.
WILL ADVISE
UPON COMPLETION.
I'VE REMOVED
THE ACCESS PLATE,
AND I'VE GOT STATIC
ELECTRIC CHARGES
DANCING ON THE INSTRUMENT.
LOOKS LIKE
AN AURORA BOREALIS IN THERE.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
YOU ARE MONITORING
THE MAGNETIC FORCE?
OH, YES, SIR.
PLEASE DO NOT TAKE
YOUR EYES OFF OF IT.
AYE, SIR.
LIEUTENANT RADHA,
ARM THE POD
JETTISON SYSTEM.
AYE, SIR.
I'LL JETTISON THE POD
AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF TROUBLE.
NOT UNTIL MY ORDER.
YES, SIR.
WARP 11.9.
MR. SCOTT, WHAT IS
YOUR SITUATION?
IT'S HARD TO SEE.
THERE'S
SO MUCH DISTURBANCE
THAT ANY ATTEMPT
TO GET AT THE FLOW
WOULD RUPTURE
THE MAGNETIC FIELD.
YOU HAVE 8 MINUTES...
41 SECONDS.
I KNOW WHAT TIME IT IS.
I DON'T NEED
A BLOOMIN' CUCKOO CLOCK.
CAPTAIN,
I'M GETTING THAT STRANGE
MAGNETIC SWEEP AGAIN
FROM ZERO
TO OFF THE SCALE.
YES.
LIKE A DOOR OPENING.
WHO HAVE YOU COME FOR
THIS TIME?
FOR YOU,
JAMES T. KIRK,
COMMANDER OF
THE ENTERPRISE.
KEEP BEHIND US, JIM.
WHY DO YOU WANT
TO KILL US?
FOR DEFENSE.
YOU ARE
CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK,
COMMANDER OF
THE ENTERPRISE.
THEN WHY DO YOU WANT
TO KILL ME?
YOU...ARE AN INVADER.
WE'RE HERE ON
A PEACEFUL MISSION.
IT'S YOU WHO HAVE
KILLED OUR PEOPLE.
WE MEAN NO HARM
TO YOU.
WE WANT TO LEAVE
PEACEFULLY.
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING
NO LIFE FORM REGISTER.
AN ANDROID?
NO, THAT WOULD GIVE
A MECHANICAL READING.
I'M GETTING NOTHING.
WHO ARE YOU?
I AM LOSIRA...
COMMANDER.
COMMANDER OF WHAT?
OF THIS STATION.
STATION?
STATION WHERE?
HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT KILLING ME?
FEEL?
KILLING...IS WRONG.
STAY BETWEEN US.
YOU MUST NOT
PENETRATE THIS STATION.
PLEASE.
I MUST TOUCH YOU.
YOU WANT TO KILL ME?
NO.
THEN WHY DO IT
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO?
I AM...SENT.
BY WHOM?
WE DEFEND THIS PLACE.
ARE THERE OTHERS
ON THIS PLANET?
THEY...ARE...
NO MORE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN ALONE?
ARE YOU LONELY?
SHE MUST BE SOMEWHERE.
SHE'S NOT
REGISTERING.
AND THERE'S
THIS POWER SURGE,
RIGHT OFF THE SCALE,
LIKE A DOOR CLOSING.
IT MUST BE
NEAR HERE.
IS THE POWER LEVEL
STILL HOLDING, JIM?
RIGHT OFF THE SCALE.
IT'S REMAINED AT A PEAK
EVER SINCE SHE DISAPPEARED.
THE ENTRANCE...IS HERE.
YOU THINK WE'RE
BEING INVITED IN?
IT CERTAINLY LOOKS LIKE IT,
AND THE INVITATION
DOESN'T EXACTLY RELAX ME.
I'D RATHER BE ON
THE ENTERPRISE.
I AGREE.
WE'VE BEEN LED HERE.
WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT WHATEVER CIVILIZATION
EXISTS ON THIS PLANET
IS IN THERE.
AND WITHOUT THE ENTERPRISE,
GENTLEMEN,
THE ONLY SOURCE
OF FOOD AND WATER
IS...IN THERE.
LET'S GO.
COMPUTER READOUT.
COMPARISON ANALYSIS
COMPLETE.
CONTINUE.
TRANSPORTER FACTOR M-7
REASSEMBLED OUTPHASE
.0009.
57 SECONDS TO GO, SIR.
UNDERSTOOD.
[SCOTTY]
MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
I'M GOING TO TRY TO CUT
THROUGH THE MAGNETIC FLOW.
BUT IF THE PROBE
DOESN'T PRECISELY
MATCH THE MAGNETIC FLOW,
THERE'LL BE AN EXPLOSION.
STARTING RIGHT...NOW.
MAGNETIC FORCE INDICATOR
JUMPING, MR. SPOCK.
MR. SCOTT, EASE OFF.
MAGNETIC FORCE HAS
DROPPED TO NORMAL, SIR.
WARP 13.2, SIR.
COMPUTER,
FOR OUTPHASE CONDITION,
WILL REVERSE FIELD
ACHIEVE CLOSURE?
AFFIRMATIVE,
IF M-7 FACTOR MAINTAINED.
MR. SCOTT, REVERSE POLARITY
ON YOUR MAGNETIC PROBE.
REVERSE POLARITY?
THAT IS CORRECT,
MR. SCOTT.
THAT'LL TAKE SOME DOING.
AND WHAT PURPOSE COULD IT--
PLEASE COMMENCE.
I'LL EXPLAIN.
YOU WERE CORRECT
IN YOUR FEEL.
THE ENTERPRISE
WAS PUT THROUGH
A MOLECULAR TRANSPORTER
AND REASSEMBLED
SLIGHTLY OUT OF PHASE.
REVERSED POLARITY SHOULD
SEAL THE INCISION.
I HAVE NO TIME FOR THEORY.
I JUST HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT.
[RADHA]
20 SECONDS,
MR. SPOCK.
I'M DOING THE BEST I CAN!
WAIT!
IT'S STUCK!
PUSH THE BUTTON!
PLEASE CONTINUE,
MR. SCOTT.
DON'T BE A FOOL!
PUSH THE BUTTON!
IT'S YOUR LAST CHANCE!
DON'T BE SENTIMENTAL!
PUSH IT!
I'M GOING TO DIE ANYWAY!
PLEASE CONTINUE.
IT'S LOOSE!
BUT THERE'S NO TIME!
PUSH THE BUTTON!
9 SECONDS,
8 SECONDS,
7 SECONDS,
6 SECONDS,
5 SECONDS,
4 SECONDS,
3 SECONDS,
2 SECONDS,
1.
MR. SPOCK, NOW.
WARP 14.1.
[BEEP]
WARP 14.
MAGNETIC FORCES STEADY.
WARP 13.9
AND DROPPING.
MR. SCOTT, YOU HAVE
ACCOMPLISHED YOUR TASK.
YOU MIGHT AT LEAST
SAY THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT PURPOSE,
MR. SCOTT?
WHAT IS IT
IN YOU HUMANS...
NEVER MIND.
THAT REQUIRES
AN OVERWHELMING
DISPLAY OF EMOTION
IN A SITUATION
SUCH AS THIS?
TWO MEN PURSUE
THE ONLY REASONABLE
COURSE OF ACTION
INDICATED, AND YET
YOU FEEL THAT
SOMETHING ELSE
IS NECESSARY.
WHO HAVE YOU COME FOR?
FORM A CIRCLE.
YOU SEE?
YOU BETTER TELL US.
TELL US!
WHO HAVE YOU COME FOR?
YOU'RE A VERY
DETERMINED WOMAN. FOR ME?
I AM FOR JAMES T. KIRK.
GENTLEMEN,
I NEED YOUR HELP.
PLEASE.
I MUST TOUCH YOU.
I BEG IT.
IT IS MY EXISTENCE.
WE'VE SEEN THE RESULTS
OF YOUR TOUCH.
BUT YOU ARE MY MATCH,
JAMES KIRK.
I MUST TOUCH YOU.
THEN I WILL LIVE AS ONE,
EVEN TO THE STRUCTURE
OF YOUR CELLS,
THE ARRANGEMENT
OF CHROMOSOMES.
THAT IS HOW YOU KILL.
YOU'LL NEVER REACH ME.
WATCH OUT!
I AM FOR McCOY.
THAT COMPUTER
MUST BE PROGRAMMING
THESE REPLICAS.
THE WOMEN MATCH
OUR CHROMOSOME PATTERNS
AFTER THEY TOUCH US.
IT'S A VERY
PAINFUL AFFAIR,
I CAN TELL YOU.
I AM FOR SULU.
SHIFT
POSITIONS.
CAPTAIN, WE CAN NO LONGER
PROTECT EACH OTHER.
SPOCK, THE COMPUTER!
DESTROY IT!
OH, MR. SPOCK,
I CERTAINLY AM
GLAD TO SEE YOU.
I THOUGHT YOU
AND THE ENTERPRISE
HAD BEEN DESTROYED.
I HAD
THE SAME MISGIVINGS
ABOUT YOU, CAPTAIN.
WE RETURNED
AND PICKED UP
YOUR LIFE-FORM READINGS
ONLY A MOMENT AGO.
RETURNED FROM WHERE?
FROM WHERE THIS BRAIN
HAD THE POWER TO SEND
THE ENTERPRISE,
990.7 LIGHT YEARS
ACROSS THE GALAXY.
WHAT A REMARKABLE
CULTURE THIS IS.
WAS, MR. SPOCK.
ITS DEFENSES WERE RUN
BY COMPUTER.
I SURMISED THAT,
CAPTAIN.
ITS MOVES WERE
IMMENSELY LOGICAL.
BUT WHAT PEOPLE
CREATED THIS?
ARE THERE ANY
REPRESENTATIVES HERE?
THERE WERE REPLICAS
OF ONE OF THEM.
BUT THAT POWER
TO RECREATE THEM
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
THAT IS A LOSS,
CAPTAIN.
WELL, YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
THOUGHT SO, MR. SPOCK,
IF YOU'D BEEN AMONG US.
[WHIRRING]
MY FELLOW KALANDANS,
WELCOME.
A DISEASE
HAS DESTROYED US.
BEWARE OF IT.
AFTER YOUR LONG JOURNEY,
I AM SORRY TO GIVE YOU
ONLY A RECORDED WELCOME,
BUT WE WHO HAVE GUARDED
THE OUTPOST FOR YOU
WILL BE DEAD BY THE TIME
YOU TAKE POSSESSION
OF THIS PLANET.
I AM THE LAST OF OUR
ADVANCE FORCE LEFT ALIVE.
TOO LATE THE PHYSICIANS
DISCOVERED THE CAUSE
OF THE SICKNESS
THAT KILLS US.
IN CREATING THIS PLANET,
WE HAVE ACCIDENTALLY
PRODUCED A DEADLY ORGANISM.
I HAVE AWAITED THE REGULAR
SUPPLY SHIP FROM HOME
FOR MEDICAL ASSISTANCE,
BUT I DOUBT NOW WHETHER
IT WILL ARRIVE IN TIME.
I WILL SET
THE OUTPOST CONTROLS
ON AUTOMATIC.
THE COMPUTER
WILL SELECTIVELY DEFEND
AGAINST ALL LIFE FORMS
BUT OUR OWN.
MY FELLOW KALANDANS,
I, LOSIRA...
WISH YOU WELL.
THE PREVIOUS SHIPS
PROBABLY SPREAD THE DISEASE
ALL THROUGH THEIR PEOPLE.
THE SUPPLY SHIP THAT
SHE WAS WAITING FOR
NEVER CAME.
ALL THESE
THOUSANDS OF YEARS,
SHE'S BEEN WAITING
TO GREET PEOPLE
WHO WERE...DEAD.
TO DO THE JOB
OF DEFENSE,
THE COMPUTER PROJECTED
A REPLICA
OF THE ONLY IMAGE
AVAILABLE--
LOSIRA'S.
THE COMPUTER
WAS TOO PERFECT.
IT PROJECTED SO MUCH
OF LOSIRA'S PERSONALITY
INTO THE REPLICA
THAT IT FELT REGRET,
GUILT AT KILLING.
THAT BOUGHT US
THE TIME WE NEEDED
TO DESTROY IT.
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN...
A REMARKABLE WOMAN.
AND BEAUTIFUL.
BEAUTY IS TRANSITORY,
DOCTOR.
HOWEVER, SHE WAS EVIDENTLY
HIGHLY INTELLIGENT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
FIVE TO BEAM UP.
I DON'T AGREE
WITH YOU, MR. SPOCK.
INDEED, CAPTAIN?
BEAUTY...
SURVIVES.