Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5725.3--
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS EN ROUTE
TO MEMORY ALPHA.
IT IS A PLANETOID
SET UP BY THE FEDERATION
SOLELY AS A CENTRAL LIBRARY,
CONTAINING THE TOTAL
CULTURAL HISTORY
AND SCIENTIFIC KNOWLEDGE
OF ALL PLANETARY
FEDERATION MEMBERS.
WITH US IS SPECIALIST
LIEUTENANT MIRA ROMAINE.
SHE IS ON BOARD
TO SUPERVISE THE TRANSFER
OF ALL NEWLY DESIGNED
EQUIPMENT
DIRECTLY FROM THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO MEMORY ALPHA.
YOU'RE THE SANEST,
THE SMARTEST,
THE NICEST WOMAN
THAT HAS EVER COME
ABOARD THIS SHIP.
ANYTHING ELSE?
ANYTHING ELSE I'LL...
I'LL KEEP TO MYSELF
FOR THE MOMENT.
Kirk: WHEN A MAN
OF SCOTTY'S YEARS FALLS IN LOVE,
THE LONELINESS OF HIS LIFE
IS SUDDENLY REVEALED TO HIM.
HIS WHOLE HEART ONCE THROBBED
ONLY TO THE SHIP'S ENGINES.
HE COULD TALK
ONLY TO THE SHIP.
NOW HE CAN SEE
NOTHING BUT THE WOMAN.
I DIDN'T THINK
MR. SCOTT WOULD GO
FOR THE BRAINY TYPE.
I DON'T THINK HE'S EVEN
NOTICED SHE HAS A BRAIN.
MR. SCOTT.
HMM?
AS SOON AS WE'RE WITHIN
VIEWING RANGE OF MEMORY ALPHA,
YOU AND LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
WILL GO TO YOUR POSITIONS
IN THE EMERGENCY
MANUAL MONITOR.
YOU'LL PREPARE FOR DIRECT
TRANSFER OF EQUIPMENT
TO MEMORY ALPHA.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE READY, SIR.
Spock: LIEUTENANT,
MAY I OFFER
MY CONGRATULATIONS
ON WHAT WILL BE
YOUR FIRST ASSIGNMENT
FOR THE FEDERATION.
YES. GOOD LUCK,
LIEUTENANT.
THANK YOU.
[BEEPING]
CAPTAIN,
I'M PICKING UP
A HIGH INTENSITY
READING.
IS THAT MEMORY ALPHA?
NO, SIR.
EXCUSE ME.
MAGNIFICATION 8.
WHAT IS THAT?
INDICATIONS
ARE A STORM, CAPTAIN,
ALTHOUGH I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE
OF SUCH GREAT INTENSITY
OR STRANGE CONFORMATION.
Kirk: READINGS?
THE SENSOR READINGS ARE
AT MAXIMUM CALIBRATION.
CAPTAIN,
IT'S APPROACHING
AT WARP FACTOR 2.6
AND ACCELERATING.
CHECK THAT.
NO NATURAL PHENOMENA
CAN MOVE
FASTER THAN
THE SPEED OF LIGHT.
Spock: IT IS DEFINITELY
DOING SO, CAPTAIN.
THEREFORE IT CANNOT BE
A PHENOMENON OF NATURE.
DEFLECTORS ON,
CONDITION YELLOW.
Uhura: CONDITION
YELLOW, SIR.
SHIELDS ACTIVATED,
CAPTAIN.
[NO VOICE]
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[NO VOICE]
MR. SULU, GET US
THE DEVIL OUT OF HERE!
FULL SCAN ON THE DISTURBANCE
THAT PENETRATED THE BRIDGE.
LIEUTENANT, ALL DECKS--
DAMAGE REPORT.
MIRA!
Kirk: DR. McCOY, EMERGENCY.
EMERGENCY.
MIRA!
[LOW-PITCHED CROAKING]
Scotty: WHAT'S THAT
YOU'RE SAYING?
[CROAKING]
WAS SHE HURT BY THE FALL
OR THE ACTION OF
THE DISTURBANCE?
I DON'T KNOW.
DID YOU NOTICE, SCOTTY?
WELL, AFTER THE
DISTURBANCE WAS OVER,
SHE JUST COLLAPSED.
HOW'S SHE DOING,
DOCTOR?
WELL, I THINK
SHE'S COMING AROUND NOW.
EASY, NOW.
EASY. YOU HAD
QUITE A FALL.
[SIGHS]
I'M--I'M FINE.
YOU LET ME BE THE JUDGE
OF THAT.
DO YOU FEEL LIKE WALKING
TO SICK BAY?
I'M FINE, DOCTOR.
REALLY I AM.
IS EVERYBODY ELSE
ALL RIGHT?
AYE, THEY ARE.
NOW, YOU JUST DO
WHAT DR. McCOY
ORDERED.
WHY? I FEEL
PERFEC--
YOU GET TO
SICK BAY, LIEUTENANT.
THAT'S AN ORDER.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN, WOULD IT
BE ALL RIGHT IF I
WENT ALONG TO SICK BAY?
NO, MR. SCOTT.
YOU STAY AT YOUR POST,
FOR THE MOMENT.
LIEUTENANT UHURA.
CAPTAIN, I--
YES, SIR?
DAMAGE REPORT.
ALL STATIONS
ARE OPERATIVE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK.
SOME EQUIPMENT
WAS TEMPORARILY
OUT OF ORDER.
MY SENSORS
WERE INOPERATIVE.
ANY DAMAGE
TO THE WARP ENGINES?
NONE, CAPTAIN.
GOOD.
FROM THE ACTION
OF THAT...STORM,
WE'LL NEED
ALL THE SPEED
WE CAN GET.
CAPTAIN,
IT WAS NOT A STORM.
Uhura: CAPTAIN.
DURING THE DISTURBANCE,
MEMORY ALPHA WAS HAILING.
I WANTED TO RESPOND,
BUT I COULDN'T MAKE
MY HAND MOVE.
Chekov: CAPTAIN.
IT WAS NOT HANDS
THAT WERE PARALYZED.
IT WAS EYES.
I COULD NOT FORCE
MY EYES TO LOOK DOWN
AND SET A NEW COURSE.
Sulu: NO, NO.
IT WAS SPEECH
THAT WAS AFFECTED.
I COULDN'T UTTER
A SOUND.
MR. SPOCK...
EXPLANATION.
ONLY OF THE RESULT,
NOT OF THE CAUSE.
IN EACH CASE,
A DIFFERENT AREA OF
THE BRAIN WAS AFFECTED.
OUR VOLUNTARY NERVE
FUNCTIONS WERE UNDER
SOME FORM OF PRESSURE.
OR ATTACK.
ATTACK MIGHT BE
A MORE PRECISE
FORMULATION, CAPTAIN.
AND LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
SEEMS MOST SUSCEPTIBLE.
ARE THE READINGS
CORRESPONDING, NURSE?
EVERYTHING APPEARS
NORMAL, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S THAT
YOU'RE DOING, NURSE?
RECORDING YOUR RESPONSES
IN THIS COMPUTER.
BUT WHY? I HAVEN'T HAD
A SINGLE RESPONSE WORTH NOTING.
LIEUTENANT, PLEASE.
WELL, HAVE I?
LIEUTENANT,
THERE ARE 430 PEOPLE
ABOARD THIS SHIP.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
THAT PASSED OUT,
AND I WANT TO KNOW WHY.
I WANT TO KNOW WHY, TOO.
YOU'RE THE DOCTOR.
YOU TELL ME.
THIS WHOLE THING IS
A NEW EXPERIENCE FOR ME.
THIS WHOLE THING
IS A NEW EXPERIENCE
FOR ALL OF US.
ALL OF YOU ARE ACCUSTOMED
TO NEW EXPERIENCES.
IT'S PART OF YOUR WORK.
I'M NOT.
SHE MIGHT HAVE
SOMETHING THERE,
DR. McCOY.
THIS IS HER FIRST
DEEP-SPACE TRIP,
AND YOU KNOW HOW
THAT AFFECTS PEOPLE.
WELL, IF WE CAN GET ON
WITH THIS, SCOTTY,
WE MIGHT MAKE
THAT DETERMINATION.
NOW, THEN, TELL ME,
WHAT DID YOU FEEL
BEFORE YOU PASSED OUT?
NOTHING.
NOTHING?
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
LIEUTENANT--
DOCTOR, THERE IS NOTHING
MORE I CAN TELL YOU.
LIEUTENANT,
YOU'RE BEING COMPLETELY
UNCOOPERATIVE!
ARE YOU PUTTING THAT
INTO MY RECORD?
IT'S NOT TRUE!
I'LL PUT THE FACTS
INTO YOUR RECORD
IF I CAN GET THEM.
AW, NOW, MIRA,
WE MUST HELP
THE DOCTOR.
TELL US
WHAT HAPPENED.
PERHAPS YOU
CAN EXPLAIN TO HER
THAT ANY CAREER SHE
HOPES FOR IN STARFLEET
REQUIRES DISCIPLINE
AND COOPERATION.
WELL, I'M SURE THAT'S WHAT
THE LIEUTENANT WANTS.
SHE JUST DIDN'T UNDERSTAND.
DID YOU, NOW, LASS?
WITH A BEDSIDE MANNER
LIKE THAT, SCOTTY,
YOU'RE IN
THE WRONG BUSINESS.
WHEN THE RECORD
OF THIS IS FORWARDED,
I'LL BE SENT BACK,
WON'T I?
OH, YOU WILL NOT!
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
THIS GETTING USED
TO SPACE TRAVEL,
THAT TAKES SOME DOING.
AND NOT EVERYBODY
TAKES TO IT.
DID YOU?
WELL, ME,
THAT'S DIFFERENT.
I WAS PRACTICALLY
BORN TO IT.
I WANT TO CONTINUE.
YOU WILL.
YOU PASSED
YOUR STARFLEET
PRELIMINARY
EXAMINATIONS.
AND THIS IS
JUST GETTING USED
TO WHAT YOU MIGHT CALL
YOUR SPACE LEGS.
I HOPE THAT'S
ALL IT IS.
CAPTAIN, I'VE PLOTTED
THE STORM'S PATH.
MR. LEMLI.
MAIN SCREEN
PROJECTION.
Sulu: ON
ITS PRESENT COURSE,
IT WILL HIT THE MEMORY ALPHA
PLANETOID AS IT DID US.
LIEUTENANT, TRY
AND WARN MEMORY ALPHA
OF THE PROXIMITY
OF THAT PHENOMENON.
GIVE ME AN E.T.A.
FOR ITS POSSIBLE IMPACT.
I CANNOT, SIR.
IT HAS THE ABILITY
TO CHANGE SPEED.
SIR, I'M UNABLE TO ESTABLISH
CONTACT WITH THE PLANETOID.
I'M HAILING ON ALL
FREQUENCIES. NO RESPONSE.
IT IS OF LITTLE
CONSEQUENCE, CAPTAIN.
MEMORY ALPHA HAS
NO PROTECTIVE SHIELDS.
NO SHIELDS?
NONE, CAPTAIN.
WHEN THE LIBRARY COMPLEX
WAS ASSEMBLED,
SHIELDING WAS
CONSIDERED INAPPROPRIATE
TO ITS TOTALLY
ACADEMIC PURPOSE.
SINCE THE INFORMATION
ON THE MEMORY PLANET
IS FREELY AVAILABLE
TO EVERYONE,
SPECIAL PROTECTION
WAS DEEMED UNNECESSARY.
WONDERFUL.
I HOPE THE STORM IS AWARE
OF THAT RATIONALE.
COMPLETING APPROACH
TO PLANETOID.
IT IS ALREADY OVER
MEMORY ALPHA,
CAPTAIN.
ITS SPEED
IS INCREDIBLE.
IT'S HITTING
THE PLANETOID.
Kirk: ARE WE WITHIN
ORBIT RANGE, MR. CHEKOV?
MAKING FINAL APPROACH.
LIEUTENANT,
TRY AND WARN THEM--
I'M SORRY, SIR.
I CAN'T BREAK THROUGH
THIS INTERFERENCE.
MR. SPOCK,
HOW MANY PEOPLE
ARE ON MEMORY ALPHA?
IT VARIES WITH THE NUMBER
OF SCHOLARS, RESEARCHERS,
AND SCIENTISTS
FROM VARIOUS
FEDERATION PLANETS
WHO ARE USING
THE COMPUTER COMPLEX.
Chekov: CAPTAIN,
WE ARE WITHIN
ORBIT RANGE.
LOCK INTO ORBIT.
Chekov:
AYE, SIR.
Sulu: IT IS LEAVING
MEMORY ALPHA,
CAPTAIN.
Spock: SENSORS GIVE NO READINGS
OF GENERATED ENERGY
FROM MEMORY ALPHA,
CAPTAIN.
ANY LIFE READINGS?
NONE.
LET'S FIND OUT WHAT'S
GOING ON DOWN THERE.
KIRK TO ENGINEERING.
MR. SCOTT, REPORT.
MR. SCOTT!
WHERE THE DEVIL IS HE?
SCOTTY, REPORT TO THE BRIDGE.
REPORT TO THE BRIDGE.
HAVE THE TRANSPORTER ROOM
STAND BY.
I'M TAKING A LANDING PARTY
DOWN THERE.
Uhura:
AYE, AYE, SIR.
SCOTT HERE.
SCOTTY,
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WHERE ARE YOU?
IN THE SICK BAY.
ARE YOU SICK?
OH, NO. I WAS JUST
CHECKING ON THE LASS.
SHE'S GOING TO BE FINE NOW.
THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH HER.
WELL, I'M RELIEVED TO HEAR
YOUR PROGNOSIS, MR. SCOTT.
IS THE DOCTOR THERE
WITH YOU, OR WILL I
FIND HIM IN ENGINEERING?
McCOY HERE, JIM.
DOCTOR,
HOW'S THE GIRL?
I THINK
SHE'S IN GOOD SHAPE.
Kirk: WELL, MR. SCOTT
SEEMS TO AGREE WITH YOU.
THE TWO OF YOU
MEET ME
IN THE TRANSPORTER
ROOM ON THE DOUBLE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL,
STARDATE 5725.6--
THE STORM HAS CLEARED
MEMORY ALPHA.
IT IS HEADING AWAY
AT INCREDIBLE SPEED.
WE HAVE BEEN UNABLE TO MAKE
CONTACT WITH THE PLANETOID.
ITS SILENCE IS OMINOUS.
WE ARE BEAMING DOWN
TO INVESTIGATE.
SOMEHOW I FIND
TRANSPORTING
INTO THE DARKNESS
UNNERVING.
SCOTTY, CAN YOU
GIVE US SOME MORE LIGHT?
I'M AFRAID THIS LIGHT
WILL HAVE TO DO, CAPTAIN.
THE GENERATOR
IS INOPERATIVE.
DAMAGE REPORT,
SPOCK.
A DISASTER FOR
THE GALAXY, CAPTAIN.
THE CENTRAL BRAIN
IS DAMAGED.
THE MEMORY CORE
IS BURNT OUT.
THE LOSS TO THE GALAXY
MAY BE IRRETRIEVABLE.
CAPTAIN!
A VERY FAINT
LIFE READING
IN THE IMMEDIATE
VICINITY, CAPTAIN.
LOCATE THEM.
KEEP THEM ALIVE.
WE NEED MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THIS ENEMY.
OVER HERE, CAPTAIN.
[LOW-PITCHED CROAKING]
BONES, CAN YOU
DO SOMETHING?
NOT A THING, JIM.
[CROAKING]
IT'S THE SAME
GARBLED SOUNDS
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE MADE
WHEN SHE FAINTED
AFTER THE STORM.
ARE YOU SURE?
ABSOLUTELY SURE.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
SULU HERE.
BEAM DOWN
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
IMMEDIATELY.
YES, SIR.
[CROAKING]
SPOCK...
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE
THAT BEFORE?
NEGATIVE.
[CROAKING]
[SILENT]
BONES?
SHE'S DEAD.
WHAT DID SHE
DIE OF?
SEVERE BRAIN HEMORRHAGING
DUE TO DISTORTION OF
ALL NEURAL SYSTEMS,
DISSOLUTION OF AUTONOMIC
NERVOUS SYSTEM,
ALL BASIC PERSONALITY
FACTORS, CAPTAIN.
THE ATTACK
WAS THOROUGH.
WHAT DID THE OTHERS
DIE OF?
EACH HAD A DIFFERENT
CENTER OF BRAIN DESTROYED,
CAUSE UNKNOWN.
A DIFFERENT CENTER
OF THE BRAIN, YOU SAY?
YES, CAPTAIN.
I CAN BE MORE DETAILED
WHEN WE RETURN TO THE SHIP
AND USE THE SHIP'S COMPUTERS.
Scotty: MIRA!
THE CAPTAIN
HAS SOME QUESTIONS.
YES, CAPTAIN?
LIEUTENANT, WHEN YOU
WERE UNCONSCIOUS,
YOU WERE...SPEAKING.
WHAT DID I SAY?
I DON'T KNOW.
THE WORDS WERE
UNFAMILIAR TO ME.
WHAT DID IT
SOUND LIKE?
THEY SOUNDED
EXACTLY LIKE
THE LAST WORDS SPOKEN
BY THE TECHNICIAN.
WHAT TECHNICIAN?
WE FOUND ONE PERSON IN THERE
JUST BARELY ALIVE.
THE REST WERE DEAD,
AND WE--
LIEUTENANT.
WE MUST GET BACK
TO THE SHIP!
WHY? TELL ME WHY.
THAT STORM--
IT'S RETURNING.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I KNOW.
YOU'LL BE KILLED IF WE STAY.
Spock: LIEUTENANT,
I ASSURE YOU,
THAT UNEXPLAINED
PHENOMENON WAS HEADED
AWAY FROM THE PLANET.
IT IS PROBABLY SEEKING
OTHER VICTIMS.
I TELL YOU,
IT WILL KILL US.
"ENTERPRISE" TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
KIRK HERE.
Sulu: BRIDGE, SIR.
THE STORM HAS REAPPEARED
ON THE LONG-RANGE SCANNER
AND IS CLOSING FAST.
WHAT'S ITS COURSE?
COMING BACK
IN THIS DIRECTION.
BEAM US UP.
MR. SULU, THIS IS
THE CAPTAIN.
GET THE "ENTERPRISE"
OUT OF HERE.
WAIT, CAPTAIN!
WE'VE LOST MIRA.
BELAY THAT ORDER,
MR. SULU.
STABILIZER.
SOMETHING'S INTERFERING WITH
THE TRANSPORTER SIGNAL.
I HAVE HER COORDINATES,
BUT SHE'S SUSPENDED IN TRANSIT.
LET ME.
Kirk: ALL RIGHT, MR. SULU,
GET US OUT OF HERE.
MR. SCOTT, CHECK
EMERGENCY MANUAL MONITOR
FOR TRANSPORTER CONTROL.
CAPTAIN, IT'S
CHANGING COURSE.
PLOT THE NEW COURSE,
MR. CHEKOV.
PRESENT COURSE
IS 126 MARK 20.
PLOT IT.
PRESENT COURSE
WILL BRING IT
ACROSS OUR STARBOARD
SIDE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, YOU MADE
A STATEMENT
THAT PHENOMENON
IS NOT A STORM.
EXPLAIN IT.
NO KNOWN CONDITIONS IN SPACE
WOULD SUPPORT THAT TYPE
OF NATURAL PHENOMENON.
WHAT IS IT?
CAPTAIN, I'M
HAVING DIFFICULTY
WITH THE SHIP'S SENSORS.
THEY SEEM TO BE
UNDER SELECTIVE ATTACK
BY THE PHENOMENON
AS THE UNFORTUNATE OCCUPANTS
OF MEMORY ALPHA WERE.
THEN DEDUCTIVE
REASONING WILL HAVE
TO BE SUBSTITUTED.
Spock: SHIP'S SENSORS ARE
OPERATING AT THE MOMENT.
PERHAPS THE ELUSIVE
CREATURE WILL NOW REVEAL
SOMETHING ABOUT ITSELF.
BUT I SAW
THOSE MEN DEAD...
IN THEIR EXACT
POSITIONS.
LISTEN TO ME.
I'VE TOLD YOU
WHAT STRANGE TRICKS
A SPACE TRIP CAN
PLAY ON YOUR MIND.
NOW, THAT'S ALL IT IS.
NO, SCOTTY.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD VISIONS
OF THE FUTURE EVENTS
BEFORE THIS?
NEVER.
WELL, IF YOU ASK ME,
NOBODY EVER HAS.
THAT SEEING OF THE FUTURE--
IT'S PURE BUNK.
YOU KNOW THAT,
DON'T YOU?
I'VE ALWAYS
BELIEVED IT.
AND YOU WERE
PERFECTLY RIGHT.
THEN WHAT IS IT, SCOTTY?
WHAT'S FRIGHTENING ME?
EVER SINCE THAT...
THAT STORM HIT,
I'VE...I'VE HAD
SUCH STRANGE THOUGHTS,
SUCH FEELINGS OF...
OF TERROR.
SPACE.
SPACE--
THAT'S ALL IT IS.
THEN I DON'T HAVE
TO REPORT IT?
IF YOU WANT TO SPEND
THE REST OF THE TRIP
IN SICK BAY.
BUT WHAT GOOD
WOULD THAT DO?
DR. McCOY CAN
NO MORE CURE IT
THAN HE CAN A COLD.
CAPTAIN, IT'S HEADING
STRAIGHT FOR US.
ACTIVATE SHIELDS.
SHIELDS ACTIVATED.
MR. CHEKOV, CHANGE COURSE
TO ONE 4 3 MARK 3
ONE 4 3 MARK 3.
STORM'S COURSE, MR. SULU?
TAKE EVASIVE ACTION.
Sulu:
EVASIVE ACTION.
HARD STARBOARD,
2 ONE 7 MARK 5.
Sulu: STILL
WITH US, SIR.
HARD PORT.
117 MARK 2.
Sulu:
STILL WITH US, SIR.
IS IT CLOSING?
Spock: NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
MAINTAINING ITS DISTANCE.
HOWEVER, IT IS MATCHING
EACH MANEUVER WE EXECUTE,
AND I AM RECEIVING INCREASING
MAGNITUDE OF ENERGY.
YOUR ANALYSIS, SPOCK.
WHAT IS IT?
NOT WHAT IS "IT,"
CAPTAIN.
WHAT ARE "THEY"?
THERE ARE 10 DISTINCT
LIFE UNITS WITHIN IT,
ALL POWERFULLY ALIVE
AND VITAL.
Kirk: WHO ARE THEY?
WHERE ARE THEY FROM?
IMPOSSIBLE TO DETERMINE
WITHOUT PROGRAMMING
FOR COMPUTER ANALYSIS.
IT'S CLEAR WE CAN'T
OUTRUN THEM.
CAN WE SHIELD
AGAINST THEM?
I DO NOT BELIEVE
THE "ENTERPRISE" SHIELDS
WOULD PROVE
AN EFFECTIVE DEFENSE.
THERE MUST BE SOME
DEFENSE WE CAN USE.
CAPTAIN, WE ARE DEALING
WITH A COMMUNITY
OF LIFE UNITS.
THEIR ATTACK IS IN
THE FORM OF BRAIN WAVES
DIRECTED AGAINST
THE BRAIN WHICH IS
MOST COMPATIBLE.
MAYBE WE CAN AVOID
ANOTHER ATTACK.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
OPEN ALL CHANNELS,
TIE IN THE UNIVERSAL
TRANSLATOR.
MR. SPOCK SAYS IT'S ALIVE.
MAYBE I CAN TALK TO IT.
Uhura: ALL CHANNELS OPEN,
TRANSLATOR TIED IN.
THIS IS CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK
OF THE U.S.S.
"ENTERPRISE."
WE WISH YOU
NO HARM.
PHYSICAL CONTACT
BETWEEN US
IS FATAL TO
OUR LIFE FORMS.
PLEASE, DO NOT
COME ANY CLOSER
TO OUR SHIP.
PERHAPS IT DID NOT
UNDERSTAND.
Sulu: CAPTAIN,
CHANGE IN VELOCITY
RECORDED.
Sulu: THEY
ARE PASSING
OUR STARBOARD SIDE
AND MANEUVERING
IN FRONT OF US.
SWITCHING
TO FORWARD SCANNER.
CAPTAIN, CHANGE
IN VELOCITY RECORDED.
IT HAS ACCELERATED
ITS APPROACH.
HELP, SCOTTY.
HELP. HOLD ME!
IT'S HAPPENING
AGAIN!
NO!
MIRA.
PERHAPS IT
UNDERSTANDS ANOTHER
KIND OF LANGUAGE.
CONDITION RED ALERT.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
PREPARE FOR
PHASER FIRING.
MIRA.
NO, SCOTTY! NO!
NO.
Kirk: LOCK IN PHASER
TRACKING CONTROLS.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
ADJUST PHASERS TO FIRE
ACROSS ITS COURSE.
DO NOT HIT IT.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
FIRE.
REACTION, MR. SULU?
NONE, SIR.
THEY'RE STILL
APPROACHING US.
APPARENTLY A SHOT
ACROSS THE BOW ISN'T
SUFFICIENTLY CONVINCING.
PREPARE TO LOCK PHASERS
INTO THE HEART OF
THE COMMUNITY.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
FIRE.
SCOTTY!
OH!
MIRA!
MIRA.
Sulu: THE PHASERS
SEEM TO HAVE STOPPED
THEIR APPROACH.
THEY'RE HOLDING POSITION.
LOCK IN FOR
ANOTHER BLAST.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
Scotty: CAPTAIN!
CAPTAIN, THE PHASER SHOTS--
THEY'RE KILLING MIRA!
KILLING
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE?
AYE. WHEN YOU
FIRED THE PHASERS,
THEY STUNNED HER
AND SHE CRUMPLED.
ANOTHER SHOT
AND YOU'LL KILL HER!
GET HER TO SICK BAY
AT ONCE.
READY FOR FIRING,
CAPTAIN.
CANCEL THAT ORDER.
ANOTHER ATTACK
ON THAT ALIEN LIFE FORM
WILL KILL
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE.
IT APPEARS SO.
IF SHE IS TO SURVIVE,
WE CAN'T ATTACK.
NOT DIRECTLY.
CAN THE COMPUTER
SUPPLY A DEFENSE
BASED ON ALL
THE DATA YOU'VE
BEEN ACCUMULATING?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO GATHER
SUFFICIENT DATA FOR THAT.
CAPTAIN, THERE IS ONLY
ONE POSSIBLE DEFENSE--
IF WE CAN FIND
AN ENVIRONMENT
WHICH IS DEADLY
TO THE ALIEN FORM.
AND YET ISOLATE
THE GIRL FROM
ITS DEADLY EFFECTS.
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO DR. McCOY.
McCoy: YES, CAPTAIN?
IS THE GIRL
WELL ENOUGH
TO BE QUESTIONED?
I CAN HAVE HER READY
IN A FEW MINUTES.
HAVE THE LIEUTENANT
AND MR. SCOTT
IN THE BRIEFING ROOM
AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
BRING ALL AVAILABLE
BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
WITH YOU.
KIRK OUT.
MR. SPOCK, COME WITH ME.
GO EASY ON HER, JIM.
SHE'S IN A PRETTY BAD STATE.
I'LL TRY.
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO BE
UNCOOPERATIVE, DOCTOR.
OF COURSE YOU DIDN'T.
I TOLD THE CAPTAIN.
WE MUST
GET TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT IS HAPPENING.
I'LL TELL YOU
EVERYTHING I KNOW.
SHIP'S INVESTIGATIVE
PROCEDURES ARE
SOMETIMES CONFUSING
TO A NEW CREWMAN.
DON'T LET US
UPSET YOU.
I TRUST ALL OF YOU
IMPLICITLY.
I WANT TO HELP.
Kirk: THIS
INVESTIGATION
HAS BEEN PROMPTED
BY 2 EVENTS.
FIRST IS THE TIME
YOU PASSED OUT
ON THE BRIDGE,
AND THE SECOND
IS WHEN WE FIRED
OUR MAIN PHASERS
INTO THAT FORCE
THAT IS ATTACKING US
AND SERIOUSLY
INJURED YOU.
YOU MUSTN'T WORRY
ABOUT HURTING ME.
NOW, THIS IS
HOW WE'LL PROCEED.
MR. SPOCK HAS ALL
THE INFORMATION
AVAILABLE TO US
ABOUT OUR ATTACKERS.
DR. McCOY HAS ACCESS
TO STARFLEET'S
EXHAUSTIVE FILES ON YOU.
A COMPARISON
OF THE TWO
MAY TURN UP
SOME IMPROBABLE CONNECTION
WHICH MAY PROTECT YOU
AND OURSELVES.
ALL RIGHT, GENTLEMEN?
DR. MCCOY,
WILL YOU PROCEED?
ROMAINE, MIRA.
LIEUTENANT.
PLACE OF BIRTH,
MARTIAN COLONY NUMBER 3.
PARENTS, LYDIA ROMAINE,
DECEASED.
JACQUES ROMAINE,
CHIEF ENGINEER,
STARFLEET, RETIRED.
MR. SPOCK, ARE YOU PREPARED
WITH THE BACKGROUND HISTORY
OF THE ATTACKERS?
I AM, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE FED
ALL OBTAINABLE DATA
TO THE MAIN COMPUTER.
IT SHOULD BE
READY TO SUPPLY
WHATEVER CONCLUSIONS
ARE POSSIBLE.
THANK YOU.
MR. SULU,
WHAT IS THE STATUS
OF OUR FRIENDS
UP THERE?
STATUS UNCHANGED.
THEY ARE STILL WITH US
AND KEEPING THE SAME DISTANCE.
CONTINUE EVASIVE
MANEUVERS.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
KIRK OUT.
DOCTOR, YOU HAVE
A MEDICAL RECORD
OF LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
AVAILABLE?
YES, CAPTAIN.
I'D LIKE A FEW ITEMS
FROM HER PSYCHOLOGICAL
PROFILE CHECKED.
ANY HISTORY OF
PSYCHOSOMATIC ILLNESS?
OCCASIONAL AND TEENAGE
ROUTINE INCIDENTS.
ANY EVIDENCE
OF INVOLUNTARY
OR UNCONSCIOUS
TELEPATHIC ABILITIES?
NONE.
ANY PATHOLOGICAL
OR UNUSUAL
EMPATHIC RESPONSES?
NO, CAPTAIN,
NOT EMPATHIC.
HOWEVER, AN EXTREMELY
FLEXIBLE
AND PLIANT RESPONSE TO NEW
LEARNING SITUATIONS
IS HIGHLY MARKED.
GO AHEAD, DOCTOR.
RIGHT AFTER OUR PHASERS
HIT THAT THING,
I GAVE LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
A STANDARD STEINMAN ANALYSIS,
AND THE RESULTS
MIGHT BE INTERESTING.
UH-HUH. GO AHEAD.
A COMPARISON OF OUR STEINMAN
WITH STARFLEET RECORDS
SHOWS THAT LIEUTENANT ROMAINE'S
FINGERPRINTS, VOICE ANALYSIS,
ALL EXTERNAL FACTORS REMAIN
EXACTLY THE SAME AS BEFORE.
HOWEVER, ACCORDING TO
2 HYPERENCEPHALOGRAMS,
HER BRAIN WAVE PATTERN
HAS BEEN ALTERED.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
THAT'S WHAT
I WAS TAUGHT.
BUT THE BCP IS JUST AS
CONSISTENT AS FINGERPRINTS.
LET'S SEE IT.
DR. McCOY, ACCORDING
TO YOUR RECORDS,
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
HAS SHOWED NO ABNORMAL
TELEPATHIC POWERS.
McCoy:
THAT'S RIGHT, SPOCK,
BUT EXCEPTIONAL PLIANCY
WAS INDICATED.
THAT MIGHT BE A FACTOR.
Spock:
AND YOU ARE SURE
THAT THIS IS
THE CORRECT SLIDE?
YES, MR. SPOCK.
THAT IS TAPE DECK "D"--
BRAIN CIRCUITRY PATTERN
OF LIEUTENANT MIRA ROMAINE.
GENTLEMEN,
IT ALSO
HAPPENS TO BE
TAPE "H"--
THE IMPULSE
TRACKING
OBTAINED
FROM THE ALIEN
LIFE UNITS.
McCoy: NURSE CHAPEL
FOLLOWED THIS EVERY
STEP OF THE WAY.
THERE CAN BE NO ERROR.
CHECK IT, SPOCK.
AS I SAID, CAPTAIN,
THIS IS THE TRACKING
OBTAINED DURING
THE LAST SHIELDED RUN.
COMPUTER,
RUN A DETAILED
COMPARISON--
BRAIN CIRCUITRY
PATTERNS,
TAPE "D"
AND TAPE "H."
Computer voice:
COMPARISON--
TAPE "D," BRAIN CIRCUITRY
PATTERNS OF LIEUTENANT
MIRA ROMAINE
AND TAPE "H," BRAIN CIRCUITRY
PATTERNS OF ALIEN LIFE UNIT
IDENTICAL.
FASCINATING.
THERE HAS BEEN NO ERROR.
DR. McCOY
IS CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS AN IDENTITY
OF MINDS TAKING PLACE
BETWEEN THE ALIEN
BEINGS AND THE MIND
OF LIEUTENANT ROMAINE.
THEIR THOUGHTS...
ARE BECOMING HERS.
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
THE ALIEN IS
NO LONGER MAINTAINING
ITS DISTANCE.
CONTINUE EVASIVE ACTION.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
KIRK OUT.
MIRA HAS TRIED TO TELL ME
ALL ALONG
THAT SHE WAS SEEING THINGS
IN ADVANCE.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
REPORT IT?
YOU DON'T REPORT
SPACE SICKNESS.
THAT'S ALL
I THOUGHT IT WAS.
WHAT DID SHE SEE?
FIRST THE ATTACK
ON THE SHIP,
THE ATTACK
ON MEMORY ALPHA,
AND...THE TIME
WE NEARLY LOST HER.
THOSE WERE ALL
ACTS CARRIED OUT
BY OUR ATTACKER.
AND...
YES, SCOTTY?
WHAT ELSE?
I THOUGHT FOR A MOMENT
THERE WAS SOMETHING ELSE,
BUT...I GUESS
I WAS WRONG.
WAS HE WRONG,
LIEUTENANT?
YES, THERE WAS
ONE OTHER TIME.
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
I SAW SCOTTY.
WHERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT WAS HE DOING?
HE WAS DYING.
NOW I UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S BEEN
HAPPENING.
I'VE BEEN SEEING
THROUGH...
THROUGH ANOTHER MIND.
I'VE BEEN FLOODED
WITH THOUGHTS...
NOT MY OWN.
THEY CONTROL ME!
OH, SCOTTY.
SCOTTY,
I'D RATHER DIE
THAN HURT YOU!
I'D RATHER DIE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW.
WHAT'S ALL THIS TALK
OF DYING?
THEY'VE CALLED THE TURN ON US
3 OUT OF 4 TIMES.
NOW, THAT'S A BETTER AVERAGE
THAN ANYBODY DESERVES.
IT'S OUR TURN NOW.
WE'LL FIGHT THEM.
SO LET'S NOT HEAR
ANYTHING MORE ABOUT DYING.
[SIGNAL FROM BRIDGE]
KIRK HERE.
SULU, CAPTAIN.
ALL EVASION TACTICS
CARRIED OUT AS ORDERED.
Kirk: WHAT SUCCESS
DID YOU HAVE?
IT'S BEEN USELESS,
CAPTAIN.
Spock: AT THEIR
PRESENT FORCE,
THEY WILL GET
THROUGH THE SHIELDS
THIS TIME, CAPTAIN.
WARP 8, MR. SULU.
YES, SIR.
THEY'LL BE HERE
VERY SOON.
THEY MAY DESTROY YOU
AND US AS THEY DID
MEMORY ALPHA.
YOU ARE
ESPECIALLY SUSCEPTIBLE
TO THEIR WILL.
BUT WE HAVE...
ONE CHANCE TO SURVIVE.
DON'T RESIST.
LET THEM BEGIN
TO FUNCTION THROUGH YOU.
IF WE CAN CONTROL
THAT MOMENT,
WE HAVE A CHANCE.
WILL YOU TRY?
TELL ME
WHAT TO DO.
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO MEDICAL LAB.
MEDICAL LAB HERE, SIR.
PREPARE THE ANTIGRAV
TEST UNITS.
LET'S GO.
Sulu: ATTENTION.
ALL PERSONNEL,
ATTENTION.
ALIEN FORCE
HAS PENETRATED THE SHIP.
TAKE DEFENSIVE ACTION.
ATTENTION, ALL PERSONNEL.
THE ALIEN BEING
HAS PENETRATED THE SHIP.
TAKE DEFENSIVE ACTION.
GENERAL QUARTERS--
SECURITY CONDITION 3.
INTRUDER ALERT.
REPEAT. GENERAL QUARTERS--
SECURITY CONDITION 3.
INTRUDER ALERT.
Kirk: AS SOON
AS SHE HAS ENTERED
THE GRAVITY CHAMBER,
SECURE ALL PORTS.
DON'T TOUCH ME, SCOTTY!
STAY AWAY.
[LOW-PITCHED CROAKING]
WE'VE LOST HER
TO THEM.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
SHE COULD KILL US ALL
IN THIS STATE.
SHE WILL, UNLESS WE
ARE ABLE TO COMPLETE
WHAT THE CAPTAIN
HAS PLANNED.
STAY WITH US,
MIRA.
PLEASE STAY!
I'M TRYING.
I WANT TO BE WITH YOU.
THEY ARE TOO STRONG.
DON'T LOSE YOURSELF
TO THEM.
HOLD ON!
I AM MIRA ROMAINE.
I WILL BE
WHO I CHOOSE TO BE.
Mira: I WI--
STAY AWAY, SCOTTY!
THEY'RE WITH ME.
THEY WILL KILL YOU.
YOU WON'T
LET THEM.
Deep voice:
SHE CANNOT STOP US.
YOU CANNOT PREVENT IT.
Scotty: MIRA...
MIRA!
CAPTAIN.
THAT'S NOT
MIRA TALKING.
CAPTAIN, WE MUST
DEAL WITH THEM
DIRECTLY,
NOW, WHILE SHE
STILL RETAINS
PARTIAL IDENTITY.
WE CAN SPEAK
TO THEM.
THEY WILL ANSWER
USING HER VOICE.
I'M CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK
OF THE SPACESHIP
"ENTERPRISE."
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
Deep voice:
YES, WE UNDERSTAND YOU.
WE HAVE SEARCHED
FOR A MILLENNIUM
FOR ONE THROUGH WHOM
WE CAN SEE AND SPEAK
AND HEAR AND LIVE OUT
OUR LIVES.
WHO ARE YOU?
WE ARE FROM ZETAR.
THAT IS ONE OF THE PLANETS
WHERE ALL HUMANOID LIFE
WAS DESTROYED.
YOU CAN'T BE
FROM ZETAR.
ALL LIFE WAS
DESTROYED THERE
LONG AGO.
YES. ALL CORPOREAL LIFE
WAS DESTROYED.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU?
THE DESIRES,
THE HOPES, THE MIND,
AND THE WILL OF
THE LAST 100 OF ZETAR.
THE FORCE OF OUR LIFE
COULD NOT BE WIPED OUT.
ALL THINGS DIE.
AT THE PROPER TIME.
OUR PLANET WAS DYING.
WE WERE DETERMINED
TO LIVE ON.
AT THE PEAK
OF OUR PLANS TO GO,
A SUDDEN FINAL DISASTER
STRUCK US DOWN,
BUT THE FORCE OF
OUR LIVES SURVIVED.
AT LAST WE HAVE FOUND
SOMEONE THROUGH WHOM
WE CAN LIVE IT OUT.
THE BODY OF THE ONE
YOU INHABIT
HAS ITS OWN LIFE TO LEAD.
SHE WILL ACCEPT OURS.
SHE WILL NOT.
SHE IS FIGHTING
FOR HER OWN IDENTITY.
HER MIND WILL ACCEPT
OUR THOUGHTS.
OUR LIVES
WILL BE FULFILLED.
WILL SHE LEARN
THE WAY THE PEOPLE
ON MEMORY ALPHA LEARNED?
WE DID NOT WISH TO KILL.
BUT YOU DID KILL.
NO. RESISTING US
KILLED THOSE PEOPLE.
WE DID NOT KILL THEM.
THE PRICE OF YOUR
SURVIVAL IS TOO HIGH.
WE ONLY WANT THE GIRL.
YOU CAN'T HAVE HER.
YOU'RE ENTITLED
TO YOUR OWN LIFE,
BUT NOT ANOTHER'S.
Mira's voice:
LIFE WAS GIVEN TO ME.
IT IS MINE.
I WANT TO LIVE IT OUT.
I WILL--
McCoy: THE GIRL'S
LIFE READING
IS BECOMING A MATCH
TO THE ZETARIANS.
SHE'S LOSING.
Deep voice: DO NOT FIGHT US.
THEY WILL NOT ACCEPT
THEIR OWN DEATHS.
THEY WILL BE FORCED
TO ACCEPT IT.
YOU WILL ALL DIE.
CAPTAIN, IF WE CANNOT
COMPLETE THE PLAN,
THEY WILL CARRY OUT
THEIR THREAT.
WE MUST GET HER
INTO THE PRESSURE
CHAMBER.
JIM, YOU REALIZE
THE PRESSURE NEEDED
TO KILL THE ZETARS
MIGHT KILL
THE GIRL, TOO.
MIRA WILL NOT
KILL ME.
[ZAP]
AAH!
I TOLD YOU
SHE WOULDN'T KILL ME.
SECURE THE CHAMBER.
NEUTRALIZE GRAVITY.
THE ZETARS ARE
GROWING STRONGER.
THE WEIGHTLESS STATE
HAS BECOME THEIR
NATURAL CONDITION.
PRESSURIZE THE UNIT.
BRING PRESSURE
TO 2 ATMOSPHERES
AND THEN INCREASE
ONE ATMOSPHERE
PER SECOND.
CONTINUE INCREASING
PRESSURE.
PRESSURE, SPOCK,
PRESSURE IS DANGEROUSLY
HIGH, CAPTAIN.
IT MAY DAMAGE HER!
CONTINUE, SPOCK.
PRESSURE.
McCoy:
WE'VE DONE IT, JIM.
THEY'RE GONE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, MIRA.
THEY'RE GONE!
REDUCE THE PRESSURE
VERY, VERY GRADUALLY, SPOCK.
WE MAY TAX MR. SCOTT'S
PATIENCE, DOCTOR.
NOW LIE PERFECTLY
STILL, LIEUTENANT.
TRY NOT TO MOVE AT ALL.
TAKE DEEP,
REGULAR BREATHS.
NOW, DON'T HOLD IT.
CONTINUE TO BREATHE DEEPLY.
IN, OUT.
THAT'S IT.
NOW, YOU'LL BE IN THERE
ANOTHER 20 MINUTES,
SO WHY DON'T YOU
JUST TRY TO RELAX?
NOW WE HAVE ALL
THE TIME IN THE WORLD.
BONES, ARE YOU
ABLE TO JUDGE
THE LONG-RANGE EFFECTS
ON LIEUTENANT ROMAINE?
WHEN THE PERSONALITY
OF A HUMAN IS INVOLVED,
EXACT PREDICTIONS
ARE HAZARDOUS.
PARTICULARLY WHERE HUMANS
ARE INVOLVED, DOCTOR.
HOWEVER, DESPITE STARFLEET
JUDGMENT OF THE PLIANCY
OF THE LIEUTENANT,
SHE PUT UP
A VALIANT STRUGGLE
TO RETAIN HER IDENTITY,
AND I FIND THAT
ENCOURAGING.
DR. McCOY
IS CORRECT, CAPTAIN.
WHILE THE TRUTH
WAS DIFFICULT TO ACCEPT,
WHEN IT WAS REVEALED,
THE GIRL REACTED WELL.
I WOULD SAY HER STRUGGLE
IN THIS EXPERIENCE
WOULD STRENGTHEN
HER ENTIRE EGO STRUCTURE.
WOULD EITHER
OF YOU CREDIT
SCOTTY'S STEADFAST BELIEF
IN HER AS A FACTOR?
YOU MEAN
LOVE AS MOTIVATION?
HMM. HUMANS DO CLAIM
A GREAT DEAL
FOR THAT
PARTICULAR EMOTION.
I SUPPOSE IT IS
POSSIBLE. HOWEVER--
THERE ARE NO HOWEVERS
ABOUT IT, MR. SPOCK.
IT WAS A FACTOR,
AND IT WILL BE
A FACTOR IN
THE GIRL'S RECOVERY.
Kirk: DO I TAKE IT
BOTH OF YOU
AGREE THAT
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
NEED NOT RETURN
TO STARBASE FOR
FURTHER TREATMENT?
WELL, I SHOULD THINK WORK
WOULD BE A BETTER THERAPY.
LOGICAL.
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO MR. SCOTT.
SCOTT HERE, SIR.
MR. SCOTT, HOW IS
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE?
BEAUTIFUL, CAPTAIN.
YES, MR. SCOTT.
DO I TAKE IT
YOU SAY THAT
SHE IS
FIT FOR DUTY?
POSITIVELY, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU.
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
SULU, CAPTAIN.
MR. SULU, SET COURSE
FOR MEMORY ALPHA.
LIEUTENANT ROMAINE
HAS A LOT OF WORK
TO DO THERE.
YES, SIR.
WELL, THIS IS
AN "ENTERPRISE"
FIRST.
DR. McCOY, MR. SPOCK,
AND ENGINEER SCOTT
FIND THEMSELVES
IN COMPLETE AGREEMENT.
CAN I STAND THE STRAIN?
[CHUCKLES]