Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5843.7.
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS
IN THE GRIP
OF A RAGING EPIDEMIC.
3 CREWMEN HAVE DIED,
AND 23 OTHERS HAVE BEEN
STRUCK DOWN BY RIGELLIAN FEVER.
IN ORDER TO COMBAT
THE ILLNESS,
DR. McCOY NEEDS
LARGE QUANTITIES OF RYETALYN,
WHICH IS THE ONLY KNOWN
ANTIDOTE FOR THE FEVER.
OUR SENSORS
HAVE PICKED UP
SUFFICIENT QUANTITIES
OF PURE RYETALYN
ON A SMALL PLANET
IN THE OMEGA SYSTEM.
WE ARE BEAMING DOWN
TO SECURE THIS
URGENTLY NEEDED MATERIAL.
REPORT.
JIM, THERE'S
A LARGE DEPOSIT,
BEARING 273--
4 KILOMETERS AWAY.
I'VE GOT 4 HOURS
TO PROCESS
THAT STUFF.
OTHERWISE
THE EPIDEMIC WILL
BE IRREVERSIBLE.
EVERYBODY ON BOARD
THE "ENTERPRISE"
WILL--
Spock: MOST STRANGE.
READINGS INDICATE
A LIFE FORM
IN THE VICINITY--
APPARENTLY HUMAN.
YET SHIP SENSORS
INDICATED
THIS PLANET
WAS UNINHABITED.
LET'S GET
THAT RYETALYN.
[WHIRRING]
INOPERATIVE.
Man: DO NOT KILL.
I'M CAPTAIN
JAMES KIRK OF--
I KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
I HAVE MONITORED
YOUR SHIP
SINCE IT ENTERED
THIS SYSTEM.
THEN IF YOU KNOW
WHO WE ARE,
YOU KNOW WHY
WE'RE HERE, MISTER...
FLINT.
YOU WILL LEAVE
MY PLANET.
DID YOU SAY YOUR
PLANET, SIR?
MY RETREAT FROM
THE UNPLEASANTNESS
OF LIFE ON EARTH
AND THE COMPANY
OF PEOPLE.
MR. FLINT...
I HAVE A SICK CREW
UP THERE.
WE CAN'T POSSIBLY REACH
ANOTHER PLANET IN TIME.
YOU CAN'T REFUSE US
THE RYETALYN.
YOU'RE TRESPASSING,
CAPTAIN.
WE'RE IN NEED.
WE'LL PAY FOR IT,
WORK FOR IT,
TRADE FOR IT.
YOU HAVE NOTHING
I WANT.
BUT YOU HAVE
THE RYETALYN
THAT WE NEED.
IF NECESSARY,
WE'LL TAKE IT.
IF YOU DO NOT LEAVE
VOLUNTARILY,
I HAVE THE POWER
TO FORCE YOU TO LEAVE...
OR KILL YOU
WHERE YOU STAND.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES OF
THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE."
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
MR. SCOTT,
LOCK PHASERS
ON TO OUR
COORDINATES.
Scott: AYE, CAPTAIN.
ALL PHASERS LOCKED ON.
MR. FLINT,
IF ANYTHING
HAPPENS TO US,
4 DEATHS...
AND THEN MY CREW
COMES DOWN
AND TAKES
THAT RYETALYN.
AN INTERESTING
TEST OF POWER--
YOUR ENORMOUS FORCES
AGAINST MINE.
WHO WOULD WIN?
Spock:
MR. FLINT,
UNLESS
YOU ARE CERTAIN,
I WOULD SUGGEST
YOU REFRAIN
FROM A MOST
USELESS
EXPERIMENT.
WE NEED
ONLY A FEW HOURS.
HAVE YOU EVER
SEEN A VICTIM
OF RIGELLIAN FEVER?
THEY DIE IN ONE DAY.
THE EFFECTS ARE
LIKE BUBONIC PLAGUE.
CONSTANTINOPLE...
SUMMER 1334.
IT MARCHED THROUGH
THE STREETS, THE SEWERS.
IT LEFT LEFT THE CITY
BY OX CART, BY SEA
TO KILL
HALF OF EUROPE.
THE RATS, RUSTLING
AND SQUEALING IN THE NIGHT
AS THEY, TOO, DIED.
THE RATS.
ARE YOU A STUDENT
OF HISTORY, SIR?
I AM.
THE "ENTERPRISE,"
A PLAGUE SHIP.
YOU HAVE TWO HOURS,
AT THE END OF WHICH
TIME YOU WILL LEAVE.
WITH ALL
DUE GRATITUDE.
M-4 WILL GATHER
THE RYETALYN
WHICH YOU NEED.
PERMIT ME
TO OFFER YOU
MORE COMFORTABLE
SURROUNDINGS.
COME IN,
GENTLEMEN.
OUR SHIP SENSORS
DID NOT REVEAL
YOUR PRESENCE HERE,
MR. FLINT.
MY PLANET IS
SURROUNDED
BY SCREENS
WHICH CREATE
THE IMPRESSION
OF LIFELESSNESS--
A PROTECTION
AGAINST THE CURIOUS,
THE UNINVITED.
THEN YOU LIVE HERE
ALONE.
EXCEPT FOR M-4,
WHICH SERVES
AS BUTLER,
HOUSEKEEPER,
GARDENER...
AND, UH, GUARDIAN.
Kirk: A MOST IMPRESSIVE
HOME, MR. FLINT.
YES. SHAKESPEARE FIRST
FOLIO, A GUTENBERG BIBLE,
CREATION LITHOGRAPHS
BY TERRUMNELIS
OF CENTAURUS VII--
THAT'S ONE OF THE RAREST
BOOK COLLECTIONS
IN THE GALAXY--
SPANNING CENTURIES.
BE COMFORTABLE,
GENTLEMEN.
HELP YOURSELVES
TO BRANDY.
DO WE TRUST HIM?
IT WOULD SEEM LOGICAL
TO DO SO FOR THE MOMENT.
WELL, I'LL NEED
TWO HOURS
TO PROCESS THAT RYETALYN
INTO ANTITOXIN.
IF THAT RYETALYN
ISN'T HERE IN ONE HOUR,
WE'LL GO PROSPECTING--
RIGHT OVER MR. FLINT,
IF NECESSARY.
THIS IS
THE MOST SPLENDID
PRIVATE COLLECTION
OF ART I'VE EVER SEEN
AND THE MOST UNIQUE.
THE MAJORITY ARE THE WORKS
OF LEONARDO DA VINCI,
RENAISSANCE PERIOD;
SOME OF THE WORKS
OF REGINALD POLLOCK,
20th CENTURY;
AND EVEN A STENN
FROM MARCOS II.
AT LAST I HAVE SEEN
OTHER HUMANS.
OTHER MEN.
ONE IS NOT HUMAN.
THE VULCAN.
SO THAT IS A VULCAN.
I WOULD LIKE
TO DISCUSS
SUBDIMENSIONAL
PHYSICS WITH HIM.
YOU'VE TAUGHT ME
ALL YOU KNOW
IN THE AREA,
AND YOU SAY
VULCANS KNOW MORE.
EVEN HE IS NOT
YOUR INTELLECTUAL
EQUAL, NOR MINE.
LET ME MEET THEM.
THEY ARE SELFISH,
BRUTAL--
A PART OF
THE HUMAN COMMUNITY
WHICH I REJECTED
AND FROM WHICH
I'VE SHIELDED YOU.
SOON THEY WILL
BE GONE.
LET ME MEET THEM.
RAYNA...
HAVE YOU BEEN
LONELY?
WHAT IS LONELINESS?
'TIS THIRST.
'TIS A FLOWER
DYING IN THE DESERT.
FLINT, DON'T TAKE
THIS OPPORTUNITY
AWAY FROM ME.
IT'S SO EXCITING.
EXCITING?
YOU HAVE NEVER MADE
A DEMAND OF ME BEFORE.
I'M SORRY.
DO NOT BE SORRY.
IT MIGHT BE
INTERESTING.
[LOW WHISTLE]
SAURIAN BRANDY--
100 YEARS OLD. JIM?
PLEASE.
[TRICORDER WHIRRING]
MR. SPOCK, I KNOW
YOU WON'T HAVE ONE.
HEAVEN FORBID
THOSE MATHEMATICALLY
PERFECT BRAIN WAVES
BE CORRUPTED BY
THIS ALL-TOO-HUMAN VICE.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I WILL HAVE A BRANDY.
DO YOU THINK
THE TWO OF US CAN
HANDLE A DRUNK VULCAN?
ONCE ALCOHOL HITS
THAT GREEN BLOOD...
IF I APPEAR DISTRACTED,
IT IS BECAUSE
OF WHAT I HAVE SEEN.
I AM CLOSE TO EXPERIENCING
AN UNACCUSTOMED EMOTION.
I'LL DRINK TO THAT.
WHAT EMOTION?
ENVY.
NONE OF THESE DA VINCI
PAINTINGS
HAS EVER BEEN CATALOGUED
OR REPRODUCED.
THEY ARE UNKNOWN WORKS,
ALL APPARENTLY AUTHENTIC
TO THE LAST BRUSH STROKE
AND USE OF MATERIALS.
AS UNDISCOVERED DA VINCIS,
THEY WOULD BE PRICELESS.
WOULD BE?
YOU MEAN YOU THINK
THEY'RE FAKES?
MOST STRANGE.
A MAN OF FLINT'S OBVIOUS
WEALTH AND IMPECCABLE TASTE
SCARCELY NEEDS
TO HANG FAKES.
YET MY TRICORDER
ANALYSIS INDICATES
THAT THE CANVAS
AND PIGMENTS USED
ARE OF CONTEMPORARY
ORIGIN.
WELL...
THIS COULD BE
WHAT IT SEEMS TO BE,
OR IT COULD BE
A COVER, A SETUP,
OR EVEN AN ILLUSION.
WELL, THAT COULD EXPLAIN
THE PAINTINGS--
SIMILAR
TO THE REAL THING.
SPOCK,
AT YOUR EARLIEST
OPPORTUNITY,
TAKE A FULL
TRICORDER READING
OF OUR HOST.
SEE IF HE'S HUMAN.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
MR. SCOTT.
Scott: AYE, CAPTAIN.
MR. SCOTT,
RUN A FULL
COMPUTER CHECK
ON MR. FLINT
AND ON THIS PLANET,
HOLBERG 917-G.
STAND BY
WITH YOUR RESULTS.
I'LL CONTACT.
AYE, SIR.
KIRK OUT.
WELL, LET'S ENJOY
THIS BRANDY.
IT TASTES REAL.
[M-4 WHIRRING]
EASY.
BONES.
[TRICORDER WHIRRING]
RYETALYN--READY
TO BE PROCESSED
INTO ANTITOXIN.
Kirk: BEAM UP
TO THE SHIP
AND START
PROCESSING.
THAT WILL NOT BE
NECESSARY, CAPTAIN.
M-4 CAN PREPARE THE RYETALYN
FOR INOCULATION
MORE QUICKLY
IN MY LABORATORY
THAN YOU COULD
ABOARD YOUR SHIP.
I WOULD LIKE
TO SUPERVISE THAT,
OF COURSE.
AND WHEN YOU ARE SATISFIED
AS TO PROCEDURES,
I HOPE YOU WILL DO ME
THE HONOR OF BEING
MY GUESTS AT DINNER.
THANK YOU,
MR. FLINT.
I DON'T THINK
WE HAVE THE TIME.
I REGRET MY EARLIER
INHOSPITALITY.
LET ME MAKE AMENDS.
GENTLEMEN...
MAY I PRESENT
RAYNA?
I...
THOUGHT
YOU LIVED ALONE.
I MEANT
THERE ARE NO OTHERS
BESIDES MY FAMILY.
DR. McCOY.
MR. SPOCK.
MR. SPOCK, I DO HOPE
WE CAN FIND A MOMENT
TO DISCUSS
FIELD DENSITY
AND ITS RELATIONSHIP
TO GRAVITY PHENOMENA.
Spock:
INDEED.
I WOULD
APPRECIATE
SUCH A TALK.
IT IS
AN INTEREST
OF MINE.
CAPTAIN KIRK.
RAYNA.
HER PARENTS
WERE KILLED
IN AN ACCIDENT
WHILE IN MY EMPLOY.
BEFORE DYING,
THEY PLACED
THEIR INFANT,
RAYNA KAPEC,
IN MY CUSTODY.
I HAVE RAISED
AND EDUCATED HER.
WITH MOST IMPRESSIVE
RESULTS, SIR.
WHAT ELSE
INTERESTS YOU
BESIDES GRAVITY
PHENOMENA, RAYNA?
EVERYTHING.
LESS THAN THAT
IS BETRAYAL
OF THE INTELLECT.
THE TOTALITY
OF THE UNIVERSE?
ALL KNOWLEDGE?
RAYNA POSSESSES
THE EQUIVALENT
OF 17 UNIVERSITY
DEGREES
IN THE SCIENCES
AND ARTS.
SHE IS AWARE
THAT THE INTELLECT
IS NOT ALL,
BUT ITS CULTIVATION
MUST COME FIRST,
OR THE INDIVIDUAL
MAKES ERRORS--
WASTES TIME
IN UNPROFITABLE
PURSUITS.
AT HER AGE,
I RATHER ENJOYED ERRORS
WITH NO NOTICEABLE
DAMAGE,
BUT I MUST ADMIT--
YOU'RE THE FARTHEST THING
FROM A BOOKWORM
I'VE EVER SEEN.
FLINT IS MY TEACHER.
YOU ARE
THE ONLY OTHER MEN
I'VE EVER SEEN.
THE MISFORTUNE
OF MEN EVERYWHERE...
AND OUR PRIVILEGE.
IF YOU WOULD
ACCOMPANY MY ROBOT
TO THE LABORATORY,
DOCTOR,
YOU CAN REST ASSURED
THAT THE RYETALYN
IS BEING PROCESSED.
McCoy:
THANK YOU, SIR.
YOUR PLEASURE,
GENTLEMEN--
CHESS? BILLIARDS?
CONVERSATION?
WHY NOT ALL 3?
[M-4 WHIRRING]
DID YOU
TEACH HER THAT?
WE PLAY OFTEN.
MAY I SHOW YOU,
CAPTAIN?
YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT SAVAGERY,
MR. FLINT.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED EARTH?
Flint: YOU WOULD TELL ME
THAT IT IS NO LONGER CRUEL,
BUT IT IS, CAPTAIN.
LOOK AT YOUR STARSHIP:
BRISTLING WITH WEAPONS;
ITS MISSION TO COLONIZE,
EXPLOIT--
DESTROY IF NECESSARY--
TO ADVANCE FEDERATION CAUSES.
[QUIETLY]
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
OUR MISSIONS ARE PEACEFUL,
OUR WEAPONS DEFENSIVE.
IF WE WERE BARBARIANS,
WE WOULD NOT HAVE
ASKED FOR RYETALYN.
INDEED, YOUR
GREETING--NOT OURS--
LACKED A CERTAIN
BENEVOLENCE.
THE RESULT OF PRESSURES
WHICH ARE NOT...
YOUR CONCERN.
YES, WELL,
THOSE PRESSURES
ARE EVERYWHERE,
IN EVERYONE,
URGING HIM TO WHAT
YOU CALL SAVAGERY--
THE PRIVATE HELLS,
THE INNER NEEDS
AND MYSTERIES,
THE BEAST
OF INSTINCT.
AS HUMAN BEINGS,
THAT IS THE WAY IT IS.
TO BE HUMAN
IS TO BE COMPLEX.
YOU CAN'T AVOID
A LITTLE UGLINESS
FROM WITHIN...
AND FROM WITHOUT.
[PIANO PLAYING]
WHY DON'T YOU
PLAY THE WALTZ,
MR. SPOCK?
TO LAUGH, TO DANCE.
RAYNA IS A MOST
ACCOMPLISHED DANCER.
OH.
MAY I HAVE
THE PLEASURE?
THANK YOU.
[DISTANT PIANO PLAYING]
[PIANO PLAYING WALTZ]
[SPOCK STOPS PLAYING]
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
YES, THERE'S
SOMETHING WRONG.
THE RYETALYN
IS NO GOOD.
IT CONTAINS IRILLIUM--
NEARLY ONE PART PER 1,000.
Spock: IRILLIUM WILL
RENDER THE ANTITOXIN
INERT AND USELESS.
MOST UNFORTUNATE
THAT IT WAS NOT
DETECTED.
I SHALL GO
WITH M-4 TO GATHER
MORE RYETALYN
AND SCREEN IT
MYSELF.
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO JOIN ME, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
TIME FACTOR,
BONES--EPIDEMIC?
NEARLY 2 1/2 HOURS.
I GUESS WE'VE GOT TIME
TO GET IN UNDER THE WIRE.
I'VE NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE
THE SPEED OF THAT ROBOT.
IT WOULD TAKE US
TWICE AS LONG
TO PROCESS THAT STUFF.
BUT WOULD WE HAVE
MADE THE ERROR?
JIM, WHAT IF
ALL THE RYETALYN
ON THIS PLANET
CONTAINS IRILLIUM?
GO WITH FLINT.
KEEP AN EYE ON...
PROCEDURES.
LIKE A HAWK.
CAPTAIN...
SOMETHING ELSE WHICH IS
RATHER EXTRAORDINARY.
THIS WALTZ
I JUST PLAYED...
IS BY JOHANNES BRAHMS.
LATER, SPOCK.
CAPTAIN, IT IS WRITTEN
IN MANUSCRIPT.
AN ORIGINAL MANUSCRIPT
IN BRAHMS' OWN HAND,
WHICH I RECOGNIZE.
IT IS TOTALLY UNKNOWN,
DEFINITELY
THE WORK OF BRAHMS...
AND YET...
UNKNOWN.
I THINK I WILL GO
TO THE LABORATORY.
THERE MAY BE A WAY
OF REVERSING
THE IRILLIUM'S
EFFECT
AND SAVING
THE EXISTING
ANTITOXIN.
STAY HERE.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN FLINT
AND McCOY RETURN.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5843.75.
HAVE I COMMITTED
A GRAVE ERROR
IN ACCEPTING
FLINT'S WORD
THAT HE WOULD DELIVER
THE ANTIDOTE TO US?
THE PRECIOUS TIME
I HAVE LET PASS
MAY RESULT IN DISASTER
FOR THE "ENTERPRISE"
AND HER CREW.
YOU LEFT US.
THE ROOM
BECAME LONELY.
IT IS A THIRST,
A FLOWER DYING
IN THE DESERT.
WHAT?
WHAT'S IN THERE?
I DO NOT KNOW.
FLINT TOLD ME
NEVER TO ENTER.
HE DENIES ME
NOTHING ELSE.
THEN WHY
ARE YOU HERE?
I DO NOT KNOW.
I COME HERE
WHEN I AM TROUBLED...
WHEN I WOULD...
SEARCH MYSELF.
ARE YOU
TROUBLED NOW?
YES.
BY WHAT?
ARE YOU...
HAPPY HERE
WITH FLINT?
HE'S THE GREATEST,
KINDEST, WISEST MAN
IN THE GALAXY.
THEN WHY
ARE YOU AFRAID?
[WHISPERING]
Rayna...
DON'T BE AFRAID.
[M-4 WHIRRING]
STOP COMMAND!
STOP!
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK.
FORTUNATELY,
THE ROBOT DID NOT
DETECT MY PRESENCE
AND DEACTIVATE
MY PHASER.
M-4 WAS PROGRAMMED
TO DEFEND
THIS HOUSEHOLD
AND ITS MEMBERS.
NO DOUBT I SHOULD HAVE
ALTERED ITS INSTRUCTIONS
TO ALLOW FOR UNAUTHORIZED
BUT PREDICTABLE ACTIONS
ON YOUR PART.
IT THOUGHT YOU WERE
ATTACKING RAYNA--
A MISINTERPRETATION.
IF IT WERE AROUND
RIGHT NOW,
IT WOULD CORRECT--
[M-4 WHIRRING]
TOO USEFUL A DEVICE
TO BE WITHOUT, REALLY.
I CREATED ANOTHER.
IT WILL NOW GO TO THE LABORATORY
AND JOIN DR. McCOY.
FASCINATING.
BE THANKFUL
THAT YOU DID NOT
ATTACK ME, CAPTAIN.
I MIGHT HAVE
ACCEPTED BATTLE,
AND I HAVE TWICE
YOUR PHYSICAL STRENGTH.
IN YOUR OWN WORDS,
IT WOULD BE
AN INTERESTING TEST
OF POWER.
HOW CHILDISH
HE IS, RAYNA.
WOULD YOU CALL HIM
BRAVE OR A FOOL?
I'M...
GLAD HE DID
NOT DIE.
OF COURSE.
DEATH,
WHEN UNNECESSARY,
IS A TRAGIC THING.
Flint: DR. McCOY'S
IN THE LABORATORY
WITH THE NEW
RYETALYN.
HE'S SATISFIED
AS TO ITS QUALITY.
MAY I SUGGEST
THAT YOU WAIT HERE
PATIENTLY--SAFELY?
YOU HAVE SEEN
THAT MY DEFENSE
SYSTEMS OPERATE
AUTOMATICALLY,
AND NOT ALWAYS
IN ACCORDANCE
WITH MY WISHES.
COME, RAYNA.
RAYNA.
COME.
I DON'T LIKE THE WAY
HE ORDERS HER AROUND.
SINCE WE ARE DEPENDENT
ON MR. FLINT
FOR THE RYETALYN,
CAPTAIN,
MAY I
RESPECTFULLY SUGGEST
THAT YOU PAY
LESS ATTENTION
TO THE YOUNG LADY
IF YOU SHOULD
ENCOUNTER HER AGAIN?
OUR HOST'S INTERESTS
DO NOT APPEAR
TO BE CONFINED
TO ART AND SCIENCE.
HE...
LOVES HER?
STRONGLY INDICATED.
JEALOUSY.
[TRICORDER WHIRRING]
YES.
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN
THE ATTACK,
BUT HE SEEMED
TO WANT US TOGETHER.
THE BILLIARD GAME...
HE SUGGESTED WE DANCE.
IT DOES
APPEAR TO DEFY
THE MALE LOGIC
AS I UNDERSTAND IT.
KIRK TO
"ENTERPRISE."
MR. SCOTT.
Scott: AYE, CAPTAIN.
REPORT ON
THE RIGELLIAN
FEVER.
NEARLY EVERYBODY ABOARD
HAS GOT IT, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE WORKING
A SKELETON CREW
AND WAITING
FOR THE RYETALYN.
Kirk: JUST A LITTLE WHILE
LONGER, SCOTTY.
REPORT ON
THE COMPUTER SEARCH.
THERE'S NO REPORT
ON MR. FLINT.
HE DOESN'T SEEM
TO HAVE ANY PAST.
THE PLANET WAS
PURCHASED 30 YEARS AGO
BY A MR. BRACK,
A WEALTHY FINANCIER
AND RECLUSE.
RUN A COMPUTER CHECK
ON RAYNA KAPEC.
STATUS--LEGAL WARD
AFTER THE DEATH
OF HER PARENTS.
Uhura: AYE, SIR.
KIRK OUT.
WE HAVE STILL A GREATER
MYSTERY, CAPTAIN.
I WAS ABLE TO RUN
A TRICORDER SCAN
ON MR. FLINT.
HE IS HUMAN,
BUT THERE ARE CERTAIN
BIOPHYSICAL PECULIARITIES.
SOME BODY FUNCTION READINGS
ARE DISPROPORTIONATE.
FOR ONE THING,
EXTREME AGE
IS INDICATED...
ON THE ORDER
OF 6,000 YEARS.
CAN YOU CONFIRM THAT,
MR. SPOCK?
I SHALL PROGRAM
THE READINGS
THROUGH DR. McCOY'S
MEDICAL COMPUTER
WHEN WE RETURN
TO THE SHIP.
TIME FACTOR.
WE MUST COMMENCE
RYETALYN INJECTIONS
WITHIN TWO HOURS
AND 18 MINUTES,
OR THE EPIDEMIC WILL
PROVE FATAL TO US ALL.
WHAT'S KEEPING
THE PROCESSING
THIS TIME?
THE DELAY MAY BE
DELIBERATE.
IT'S AS THOUGH
HE'S KEEPING US HERE
FOR SOME REASON.
Spock:
MOST INTERESTING.
OUR HOST APPEARS
TO WISH US
TO LINGER,
YET HE IS...
APPREHENSIVE.
IT IS LOGICAL
TO ASSUME
THAT WE ARE BEING
MONITORED
AND THAT HE IS AWARE
OF OUR EVERY MOVE.
YOU SENT THE ROBOT
TO KILL HIM.
IT CAME
TO PROTECT YOU.
MY MIND COULD NOT
HAVE SUMMONED IT.
I WAS NOT FRIGHTENED.
IT WAS
DEFECTIVE THEN.
I WOULD HAVE
DESTROYED IT MYSELF.
HAVE I LIED TO YOU?
NEVER.
BELIEVE WHAT I SAY.
I WOULD NOT WANT
CAPTAIN KIRK DEAD.
WHAT DID YOU FEEL?
YOU WILL LET THEM
HAVE THE RYETALYN?
YES.
GO TO THEM
IF YOU WISH.
SAY YOUR FAREWELLS.
KIRK HERE.
Scott: MR. SCOTT, SIR.
THERE'S NO RECORD
OF A RAYNA KAPEC
IN FEDERATION
LEGAL BANKS.
NO AWARD
OF CUSTODY?
NO BACKGROUND AT ALL
IN ANY COMPUTER BANKS...
LIKE FLINT.
KIRK OUT.
PEOPLE
WITHOUT A PAST.
WHAT HOLD DOES
HE HAVE OVER HER?
CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SUGGEST
THAT OUR IMMEDIATE CONCERN
IS THE RYETALYN.
LET'S FIND McCOY.
Rayna: CAPTAIN.
I'LL MEET YOU
IN THE LAB.
I'VE COME TO SAY
GOOD-BYE.
I DON'T WANT
TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
A LAST TENDER ENCOUNTER,
CAPTAIN KIRK,
TO END YOUR USEFULNESS.
I TELL YOU, SPOCK--
I WAS WAITING
FOR THE ROBOT TO FINISH
THE PROCESSING.
AND THE NEXT THING
I KNEW, IT WAS GONE,
AND SO WAS THE RYETALYN.
INTERESTING.
OBVIOUSLY
MR. FLINT
IS NOT YET
READY FOR US
TO DEPART.
WELL, I THINK
WE'D BETTER TELL JIM.
THE CAPTAIN
WANTED US
TO WAIT HERE.
COME WITH ME.
I...
I OFFER YOU
HAPPINESS.
I'VE KNOWN
SECURITY HERE.
CHILDHOOD MUST END.
YOU LOVE ME,
NOT FLINT.
FLINT LIED.
THE RYETALYN
ISN'T HERE.
PICKING UP
TRICORDER READINGS, CAPTAIN.
APPARENTLY THE RYETALYN
IS BEHIND THIS DOOR.
WHY IS FLINT PLAYING
TRICKS ON US?
APPARENTLY WE'RE
SUPPOSED TO GO IN
AND GET IT...
IF WE CAN.
WELL, LET'S
NOT DISAPPOINT
THE CHESS MASTER.
PHASERS ON FULL.
CAPTAIN.
I SHALL GET
THE RYETALYN.
WHY YOU?
THERE MAY BE
DANGERS WITHIN.
LET'S FIND OUT.
LET ME GO ALONE,
CAPTAIN.
McCoy: WHY?
GET TO THE POINT, SPOCK,
IF THERE IS ONE.
WE'LL ALL GO.
THE RYETALYN.
Kirk, voice-over: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5843.8.
WE HAVE ACCOMPLISHED
OUR MISSION
AND HAVE THE RYETALYN
READY TO COMBAT
THE EPIDEMIC
ABOARD THE "ENTERPRISE,"
BUT WE HAVE ALSO DISCOVERED
OUR BENEFACTOR'S SECRET.
HE HAS CREATED
THE PERFECT WOMAN.
HER ONLY FLAW...
SHE'S NOT HUMAN.
PHYSICALLY HUMAN...
BUT NOT HUMAN.
THESE ARE
EARLIER VERSIONS
OF RAYNA, JIM.
SHE'S AN ANDROID.
Flint: CREATED HERE
BY MY HAND.
HERE THE CENTURIES
OF LONELINESS WERE TO END.
YOUR COLLECTION
OF LEONARDO DA VINCI
MASTERPIECES, MR. FLINT--
THEY APPEAR TO HAVE
BEEN RECENTLY PAINTED
ON CONTEMPORARY CANVAS
WITH CONTEMPORARY
MATERIALS.
AND ON YOUR PIANO...
A WALTZ
BY JOHANNES BRAHMS--
AN UNKNOWN WORK
IN MANUSCRIPT
WRITTEN IN MODERN INK,
YET ABSOLUTELY AUTHENTIC,
AS ARE YOUR PAINTINGS.
I...
AM BRAHMS.
AND DA VINCI.
YES.
HOW MANY OTHER NAMES
SHALL WE CALL YOU?
SOLOMON,
ALEXANDER, LAZARUS,
METHUSELAH,
MERLIN, OBBRUMSON,
100 OTHER NAMES
YOU DO NOT KNOW.
YOU WERE BORN...
IN THAT REGION OF EARTH
LATER CALLED MESOPOTAMIA
IN THE YEAR 3834 B.C.,
AS THE MILLENNIA
ARE RECKONED.
I WAS OCARIN--
A SOLDIER, A BULLY,
AND A FOOL.
I FELL IN BATTLE,
PIERCED IN THE HEART...
AND DID NOT DIE.
McCoy: INSTANT
TISSUE REGENERATION,
COUPLED WITH SOME PERFECT FORM
OF BIOLOGICAL RENEWAL.
YOU LEARNED
THAT YOU WERE IMMORTAL AND--
AND TO CONCEAL IT--
TO LIVE SOME
PORTION OF A LIFE...
TO PRETEND TO AGE
AND THEN MOVE ON
BEFORE MY NATURE
WAS SUSPECTED.
YOUR WEALTH
AND YOUR INTELLECT
ARE THE PRODUCT
OF CENTURIES
OF ACQUISITION.
YOU KNEW THE GREATEST
MINDS IN HISTORY.
GALILEO, SOCRATES,
MOSES.
I HAVE MARRIED
A HUNDRED TIMES, CAPTAIN--
SELECTED,
LOVED, CHERISHED,
CARESSED A SMOOTHNESS,
INHALED A BRIEF FRAGRANCE...
THEN AGE, DEATH,
THE TASTE OF DUST.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
Spock: YOU WANTED
A PERFECT ULTIMATE
WOMAN...
AS BRILLIANT...
AS IMMORTAL
AS YOURSELF.
YOUR MATE
FOR ALL TIME.
DESIGNED
BY MY HEART.
I COULD NOT
LOVE HER MORE.
SPOCK, YOU KNEW?
I HAD HOPED
I WAS WRONG.
YOU CANNOT LOVE
AN ANDROID, CAPTAIN.
I LOVE HER.
SHE IS MY HANDIWORK,
MY PROPERTY.
SHE IS WHAT I DESIRE.
YOU BROUGHT ME HERE
TO LEARN THIS?
DOES SHE KNOW?
SHE WILL NEVER KNOW.
LET'S GO.
YOU WILL STAY.
WHY?
WE HAVE DISCOVERED
WHAT HE IS, CAPTAIN.
IF YOU LEAVE,
THE CURIOUS
WOULD FOLLOW--
THE FOOLISH, THE MEDDLERS,
THE OFFICIALS, THE SEEKERS.
MY PRIVACY WAS MY OWN.
ITS INVASION WILL
BE ON YOUR HEAD.
WE CAN REMAIN
SILENT.
THE DISASTER
OF INTERVENTION, SPOCK--
I'VE KNOWN IT.
I WILL NOT RISK IT.
KIRK TO "ENTERPRISE."
CLEAR OUT OF THE AREA.
INFORM STARFLEET COMMAND.
"ENTERPRISE"!
SCOTTY!
THEY CANNOT ANSWER,
CAPTAIN.
[LOUD WHIRRING]
MY CREW.
THE TEST OF POWER.
YOU HAD NO CHANCE.
IT IS TIME FOR YOU
TO JOIN YOUR CREW.
YOU'D WIPE OUT
400 LIVES? WHY?
I HAVE SEEN
100 BILLION FALL.
I KNOW DEATH
BETTER THAN ANY MAN.
I'VE TOSSED ENEMIES
INTO HIS GRASP...
AND I KNOW MERCY.
YOUR CREW IS NOT DEAD,
BUT SUSPENDED.
WORSE THAN DEAD!
RESTORE THEM.
RESTORE MY SHIP!
IN TIME--A THOUSAND,
TWO THOUSAND YEARS.
YOU WILL
KNOW THE FUTURE,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU HAVE BEEN
SUCH MEN.
YOU'VE KNOWN
AND CREATED
SUCH BEAUTY.
YOU'VE WATCHED
YOUR RACE EVOLVE
FROM CRUELTY
AND BARBARISM
THROUGHOUT YOUR
ENORMOUS LIFE,
AND YET NOW YOU
WOULD DO THIS
TO US?
THE FLOWERS
OF MY PAST.
I HOLD THE NETTLES
OF THE PRESENT.
I AM FLINT NOW
WITH MY NEEDS!
WHAT NEEDS?
TONIGHT...
I HAVE SEEN
SOMETHING WONDROUS--
SOMETHING
I'VE WAITED FOR,
LABORED FOR.
NOTHING MUST
ENDANGER IT.
AT LAST RAYNA'S
EMOTIONS HAVE
STIRRED TO LIFE.
NOW THEY WILL
TURN TO ME
IN THIS SOLITUDE
WHICH I PRESERVE.
Rayna: NO.
RAYNA.
YOU MUST NOT
DO THIS TO THEM.
I MUST.
WHAT WILL YOU
FEEL FOR HIM
AFTER WE ARE GONE?
ALL EMOTIONS ARE
IN PLAY, MR. FLINT.
YOU HARM US,
SHE HATES YOU.
GIVE ME BACK
MY SHIP.
YOUR SECRET IS
SAFE WITH US.
THAT'S WHY
YOU DELAYED
THE PROCESSING
OF THE RYETALYN.
YOU REALIZED
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
YOU KEPT US
TOGETHER--
RAYNA AND ME...
BECAUSE YOU KNEW
I COULD BRING
HER EMOTIONS ALIVE.
AND NOW YOU'RE JUST
GOING TO TAKE OVER.
I SHALL TAKE
WHAT IS MINE...
WHEN SHE COMES
TO ME.
WE ARE
MATED, CAPTAIN--
ALIKE, IMMORTAL.
YOU MUST FORGET
YOUR FEELINGS
IN THIS MATTER,
WHICH IS
QUITE IMPOSSIBLE
FOR YOU.
IMPOSSIBLE!
IMPOSSIBLE.
FROM THE BEGINNING,
YOU USED ME.
I CAN'T LOVE HER...
BUT I DO LOVE HER.
AND SHE LOVES ME.
NO!
CAPTAIN, YOUR
PRIMITIVE IMPULSES
WILL NOT ALTER
THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
STAY OUT OF THIS.
WE'RE FIGHTING OVER A WOMAN.
NO, YOU'RE NOT
FOR SHE IS NOT.
I...
CANNOT BE THE CAUSE
OF THIS.
I WILL NOT BE THE CAUSE
OF THIS!
PLEASE STOP.
Rayna: STOP!
I CHOOSE...
WHERE I WANT TO GO...
WHAT I WANT TO DO.
I CHOOSE.
I...
CHOOSE.
RAYNA!
NO.
DO NOT ORDER ME.
NO ONE CAN
ORDER ME.
SHE'S HUMAN.
DOWN TO THE LAST
BLOOD CELL,
SHE'S HUMAN.
DOWN TO THE LAST
THOUGHT.
HOPE, ASPIRATION,
EMOTION. SHE'S HUMAN!
Kirk: THE HUMAN SPIRIT
IS FREE.
YOU HAVE NO POWER
OF OWNERSHIP.
SHE'S FREE TO DO
AS SHE WISHES.
GENTLEMEN,
I URGE YOU
TO STOP.
THERE IS
A DANGER.
NO MAN BEATS ME.
I DON'T WANT
TO BEAT YOU.
THIS IS
NO TEST OF POWER.
RAYNA BELONGS
TO HERSELF,
AND SHE CLAIMS
THE HUMAN RIGHT OF CHOICE...
TO BE...
AS SHE WILLS...
TO DO AS SHE WILLS,
TO THINK AS SHE WILLS!
THAT'S WHAT
I'VE WORKED FOR.
RAYNA...
COME WITH ME.
STAY.
I...
WAS NOT...
HUMAN.
NOW...
I...
LOVE.
YOU CAN'T DIE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
SHE LOVED YOU,
CAPTAIN.
AND YOU, TOO,
MR. FLINT,
AS A MENTOR--
EVEN AS A FATHER.
THERE WAS NOT
ENOUGH TIME FOR HER
TO ADJUST
TO THE AWFUL POWER
AND CONTRADICTIONS
OF HER NEWFOUND
EMOTIONS.
SHE COULD NOT BEAR
TO HURT EITHER
OF YOU.
THE JOYS OF LOVE
MADE HER HUMAN,
AND THE AGONIES
OF LOVE
DESTROYED HER.
SPOCK.
THE EPIDEMIC
IS REDUCED
AND NO LONGER
A THREAT.
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS
ON COURSE 513
MARK 7,
AS YOU ORDERED.
A VERY OLD...
AND LONELY MAN...
AND A YOUNG...
AND LONELY MAN.
WE PUT ON A PRETTY POOR
SHOW, DIDN'T WE?
IF ONLY
I COULD FORGET.
JIM--
OH. THANK HEAVEN.
SLEEPING AT LAST.
YOUR REPORT, DOCTOR.
OH. THOSE TRICORDER
READINGS ON MR. FLINT
ARE FINALLY CORRELATED.
HE'S DYING.
SEE, FLINT,
IN LEAVING EARTH
WITH ALL OF ITS
COMPLEX FIELDS
WITHIN WHICH
HE WAS FORMED,
SACRIFICED
IMMORTALITY.
HE'LL LIVE
THE REMAINDER
OF A NORMAL
LIFE SPAN, THEN DIE.
ON THAT DAY,
I SHALL MOURN.
DOES HE KNOW?
YES. I TOLD HIM
MYSELF.
HE INTENDS TO DEVOTE
THE REMAINDER
OF HIS YEARS
AND GREAT ABILITIES
TO THE IMPROVEMENT
OF THE HUMAN
CONDITION,
AND WHO KNOWS
WHAT HE MIGHT
COME UP WITH?
INDEED.
WELL, I GUESS
THAT'S ALL.
I CAN TELL JIM
LATER, OR YOU CAN.
CONSIDERING
HIS OPPONENT'S
LONGEVITY...
TRULY AN ETERNAL
TRIANGLE.
YOU WOULDN'T
UNDERSTAND THAT,
WOULD YOU, SPOCK?
YOU SEE, I FEEL
SORRIER FOR YOU
THAN I DO FOR HIM
BECAUSE YOU'LL NEVER
KNOW THE THINGS
THAT LOVE CAN
DRIVE A MAN TO--
THE ECSTASIES,
THE MISERIES,
THE BROKEN RULES,
THE DESPERATE
CHANCES,
THE GLORIOUS
FAILURES,
AND THE GLORIOUS
VICTORIES.
ALL OF THESE THINGS
YOU'LL NEVER KNOW
SIMPLY BECAUSE
THE WORD "LOVE"
ISN'T WRITTEN
INTO YOUR BOOK.
GOOD NIGHT, SPOCK.
GOOD NIGHT, DOCTOR.
I DO WISH HE COULD
FORGET HER.
FORGET.