Spock: IT IS DEFINITELY
THE STOLEN
SPACE CRUISER, CAPTAIN.
THE AURORA.
I READ 6 ABOARD.
HAILING FREQUENCIES.
AURORA, THIS IS
THE U.S.S. ENTERPRISE,
CAPTAIN JAMES T.
KIRK COMMANDING.
ACKNOWLEDGE.
AURORA, THIS IS
THE ENTERPRISE.
DO YOU READ ME?
THEY ARE RECEIVING
US, CAPTAIN.
I READ NO EVIDENCE
OF MALFUNCTION.
REPEAT--FEDERATION ORDERS
TO DETAIN YOU FOR--
Sulu: THEY'RE
VEERING OFF, SIR.
CHANGE COURSE.
PURSUE AND OVERTAKE.
AYE, AYE, SIR.
STAND BY ON TRACTOR BEAMS.
STANDING BY, SIR.
IF IT CONTINUES
ON COURSE,
IT WILL ENTER
ROMULAN SPACE.
ENGAGE.
Sulu: TRACTOR BEAM
ENGAGED.
BRING THEM IN.
THEY'VE NOT
GONE FAR, SIR.
THEY'RE STRUGGLING
TO ESCAPE.
THEIR ENGINES ARE SERIOUSLY
OVERHEATING, CAPTAIN.
AURORA, CUT POWER.
YOU ARE OVERTAXING
YOUR SHIP.
Spock: POWER
APPROACHING CRITICAL.
THEY CANNOT CONTINUE.
EMERGENCY POWER
TO TRACTOR BEAMS.
BRIDGE TO
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
SCOTTY, ARE YOU READY
TO TRANSPORT?
AYE, CAPTAIN.
POWER BEYOND CRITICAL.
EXPLOSION IS IMMINENT.
ARE WE WITHIN
TRANSPORTATION RANGE?
NOT YET, SIR.
AURORA PERSONNEL, STAND BY
TO BE TRANSPORTED ABOARD.
ENERGIZE.
ARE THEY ABOARD?
SCOTTY...
AYE, CAPTAIN.
THEY ARE.
AND A NICE LOT, TOO.
SPACE...
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO
WHERE NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5832.3.
THE SON OF THE CATULLAN
AMBASSADOR IS ONE OF 6
WE HAVE BEAMED ABOARD
FROM THE STOLEN CRUISER AURORA.
WE HAVE BEEN ORDERED TO
HANDLE HIM WITH EXTREME DELICACY
BECAUSE THE TREATY NEGOTIATIONS
NOW IN PROGRESS
BETWEEN THE FEDERATION AND
CATULLA ARE IN A CRUCIAL PHASE.
SCOTTY, TAKE THEM
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
Woman, on intercom:
WE ARE NOT IN THE MOOD,
HERBERT.
IRINA?
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
TAKE THIS FOR ME.
Man, on intercom:
NO, HERBERT.
IT'S NO GO.
All, on intercom:
NO GO! NO GO...
WHAT'S GOING ON?
Scott, on intercom:
THEY REFUSE, SIR.
WHY?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
THEY'RE JUST
SITTING ON THE FLOOR,
THE LOT OF THEM.
YOU CAN HEAR
THEM YOURSELF.
SHALL I SEND
FOR SECURITY?
NO, I'LL BE RIGHT DOWN.
MR. SPOCK--
All: NO GO! NO GO!
NO GO! NO GO!
NO GO! NO GO! NO GO! NO GO!
NO GO! NO GO! NO GO--
WHICH ONE OF YOU
IS TONGO RAD?
YOU CAN THANK
YOUR FATHER'S INFLUENCE
FOR THE FACT THAT
YOU'RE NOT UNDER ARREST.
IN ADDITION TO PIRACY,
YOU'VE LEFT YOURSELF OPEN
TO CHARGES OF VIOLATING
FLIGHT REGULATIONS,
ENTERING HOSTILE SPACE,
AND ENDANGERING
THE LIVES OF OTHERS,
AS WELL AS YOUR OWN.
I'M BLEEDING.
IN ADDITION, YOU'VE CAUSED
AN INTERSTELLAR INCIDENT...
WHICH MAY HAVE
DESTROYED EVERYTHING
THAT'S BEEN NEGOTIATED
BETWEEN YOUR PLANET
AND THE FEDERATION.
YOU'VE GOT
A HARD LIP, HERBERT.
IF YOU HAVE AN EXPLANATION,
I AM PREPARED TO HEAR IT.
WELL, MR. SPOCK,
TAKE THEM TO SICK BAY
FOR A MEDICAL CHECK.
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN
RADIATION FROM
THE EXPLOSION.
CAPTAIN...
WITH YOUR PERMISSION...
BY ALL MEANS.
ONE.
WE ARE ONE.
Spock:
ONE IS THE BEGINNING.
ARE YOU ONE,
HERBERT?
I AM NOT HERBERT.
HE'S NOT HERBERT.
WE REACH.
IF YOU WILL STATE
YOUR PURPOSE AND
YOUR OBJECTIVES,
PERHAPS WE CAN ARRIVE
AT A MUTUAL UNDERSTANDING.
IF YOU UNDERSTAND ONE...
YOU KNOW OUR PURPOSE.
I WOULD PREFER
THAT YOU STATE IT.
WE TURN OUR BACKS
ON CONFUSION
AND SEEK THE BEGINNING.
WHAT IS
YOUR DESTINATION?
THE PLANET EDEN.
THAT PLANET
IS A MYTH.
AND WE PROTEST AGAINST
BEING HARASSED, PURSUED,
ATTACKED, SEIZED,
AND TRANSPORTED HERE
AGAINST OUR WISHES.
RIGHT, BROTHER.
WE DO NOT RECOGNIZE
FEDERATION REGULATIONS,
NOR THE EXISTENCE
OF HOSTILITIES.
WE RECOGNIZE NO AUTHORITY
SAVE THAT WITHIN OURSELVES.
WELL, WHETHER YOU RECOGNIZE
AUTHORITY OR NOT,
I AM IT ON THIS SHIP.
I AM UNDER ORDERS
TO TRANSPORT YOU BACK
TO STARBASE PEACEABLY.
FROM THERE, YOU'LL BE FERRIED
TO YOUR VARIOUS PLANETS.
BECAUSE OF MY ORDERS,
YOU ARE NOT PRISONERS,
BUT MY GUESTS.
I EXPECT YOU
TO BEHAVE AS SUCH.
OH, HERBERT,
YOU ARE STIFF!
[LAUGHTER]
MR. SPOCK, YOU SEEM TO
UNDERSTAND THESE PEOPLE.
YOU WILL DEAL WITH THEM.
WE RESPECTFULLY
REQUEST THAT YOU
TAKE US TO EDEN.
AND AFTER THEY ARE
FINISHED IN SICK BAY,
SEE TO IT THAT THEY
ARE ESCORTED BACK TO
THEIR PROPER QUARTERS
AND GIVEN WHATEVER
CARE THEY NEED.
Spock:
YES, CAPTAIN.
WE RESPECTFULLY REQUEST
THAT YOU TAKE US TO EDEN.
HMM...I HAVE ORDERS
TO THE CONTRARY.
THIS IS NOT
A PASSENGER SHIP.
HERBERT! HERBERT!
All: HERBERT! HERBERT!
HERBERT!
HERBERT! HERBERT!
HERBERT! HERBERT! HERBERT!
LIEUTENANT PALMER,
NOTIFY STARBASE
WE HAVE THE 6 ABOARD
WHO STOLE
THE SPACE CRUISER AURORA.
REGRETTABLY, THE SPACE CRUISER
ITSELF WAS DESTROYED.
AYE, SIR.
PERSONAL NOTE FOR
THE CATULLAN AMBASSADOR--
HIS SON IS SAFE.
CAPTAIN.
YES, WHAT IS IT?
SIR, I BELIEVE
I KNOW ONE OF THEM.
AT LEAST, I THINK
I RECOGNIZE HER VOICE.
HER NAME IS
IRINA GALLIULIN.
WE WERE IN STARFLEET
ACADEMY TOGETHER.
ONE OF THOSE
WAS IN THE ACADEMY?
YES, SIR.
SHE...DROPPED OUT.
SHE...
DO YOU WISH TO SEE HER?
PERMISSION
TO LEAVE YOUR POST.
THANK YOU, SIR.
ARE THEY
IN THE SICK BAY?
YES, CAPTAIN.
MR. SPOCK...
DO THEY REALLY BELIEVE
THAT EDEN EXISTS?
MANY MYTHS ARE BASED
ON TRUTH, CAPTAIN,
AND THEY ARE NOT
UNINTELLIGENT.
THEIR LEADER,
DR. SEVRIN, IS A MAN--
DR. SEVRIN
IS THEIR LEADER?
YES--A BRILLIANT
RESEARCH ENGINEER
IN THE FIELDS
OF ACOUSTICS,
COMMUNICATIONS,
AND ELECTRONICS ON TIBURON.
HE WAS DISMISSED
FROM HIS POST
WHEN HE STARTED
THIS MOVEMENT.
TONGO RAD
INHERITS HIS FATHER'S
EXTRAORDINARY ABILITIES
IN THE FIELD
OF SPACE STUDIES.
BUT...THEY'VE
REJECTED ALL THAT
AND ALL THAT THIS
TECHNOLOGY PROVIDES,
AND THEY SEEK
THE PRIMITIVE.
THERE ARE MANY WHO
ARE...UNCOMFORTABLE
WITH WHAT
WE HAVE CREATED.
IT IS ALMOST
A BIOLOGICAL REBELLION,
A PROFOUND REVULSION AGAINST
THE PLANNED COMMUNITIES,
THE PROGRAMMING,
THE STERILIZED,
ARTFULLY BALANCED
ATMOSPHERES.
THEY HUNGER FOR AN EDEN...
WHERE SPRING COMES.
ALL DO...
THE CAVE IS
DEEP IN OUR MEMORY.
YES, THAT IS
TRUE, CAPTAIN.
BUT WE DON'T STEAL
SPACE CRUISERS
AND ACT LIKE
IRRESPONSIBLE CHILDREN.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO
SYMPATHETIC TOWARD THEM?
IT IS NOT...
SYMPATHY SO MUCH AS
CURIOSITY, CAPTAIN,
A WISH TO UNDERSTAND.
THEY REGARD THEMSELVES
AS ALIENS
IN THEIR OWN WORLDS,
A CONDITION WITH WHICH
I AM SOMEWHAT FAMILIAR.
SPOCK...
WHAT DOES
"HERBERT" MEAN?
IT IS, UH...
SOMEWHAT, UM...
UNCOMPLIMENTARY,
CAPTAIN.
HERBERT WAS
A MINOR OFFICIAL...
NOTORIOUS FOR HIS
RIGID AND LIMITED
PATTERNS OF THOUGHT.
WELL, I SHALL TRY TO BE
LESS RIGID IN MY THINKING.
[PLAYING HARPSICHORDLIKE MUSIC]
♪ LOOKIN' FOR THE GOOD LAND ♪
♪ GOIN' ASTRAY ♪
♪ DON'T CRY ♪
♪ OH, I CAN'T HAVE HONEY ♪
♪ AND I CAN'T HAVE CREAM ♪
♪ GONNA LIVE, NOT DIE ♪
♪ STAND IN THE MIDDLE
OF IT ALL ONE DAY ♪
♪ LOOK AT IT SHINING
ALL AROUND ME AND SAY ♪
♪ I'M HERE ♪
♪ IN THE GOOD LAND
IN THE NEW LAND ♪
♪ I'M HERE ♪
[MUSIC STOPS]
EXCUSE ME.
IS IRINA GALLIULIN
WITH YOU?
SHE'S GETTING
HER PHYSICAL.
♪ GONNA CRACK MY KNUCKLES
AND JUMP FOR JOY ♪
♪ I GOT A CLEAN BILL OF HEALTH
FROM DR. McCOY ♪
HA HA HA!
YOU KNOW IRINA?
Rad:
SAY, TELL ME--
WHY DO YOU WEAR
ALL THOSE CLOTHES?
HOW DO YOU BREATHE?
[NURSE CHAPEL SIGHS]
YOU'RE NEXT.
Chekov: IRINA.
PAVEL ANDREIVICH.
I HAD THOUGHT WE MIGHT
ENCOUNTER EACH OTHER.
YOU KNEW I WAS
ON THE ENTERPRISE?
I HAD HEARD.
IRINA...WHY...
COME.
HOW COULD YOU
DO THIS TO YOURSELF?
YOU WERE A SCIENTIST.
AND NOW...LOOK AT YOU.
LOOK AT YOURSELF,
PAVEL.
WHY DID YOU DO IT?
WHY DID YOU?
I AM PROUD
OF WHAT I AM.
I BELIEVE IN WHAT I DO.
CAN YOU SAY THAT?
YES.
OH, WE SHOULD NOT TEAR
AT EACH OTHER SO, PAVEL.
WE SHOULD
MEET AGAIN IN JOY.
TODAY WHEN I FIRST
KNEW IT WAS YOUR SHIP
THAT FOLLOWED US,
I THOUGHT OF YOU
AND WONDERED WHAT
I WOULD FIND.
AND I REMEMBERED SO MUCH.
IN SPITE OF THAT UNIFORM,
I STILL SEE THE SAME
PAVEL I USED TO KNOW.
ARE YOU HAPPY
IN WHAT YOU DO?
YES.
THEN I ACCEPT
WHAT YOU DO.
YOU EVEN TALK
LIKE THEM.
WHY DID YOU GO AWAY?
IT WAS YOU WHO WENT.
I CAME BACK
TO LOOK FOR YOU.
I LOOKED...
WHERE DID YOU GO?
I STAYED IN THE CITY...
WITH FRIENDS.
YOU NEVER FELT
AS I DID. NEVER.
I DID.
YOU DON'T HAVE IT IN
YOU TO FEEL SO MUCH.
EVEN WHEN WE WERE CLOSE,
YOU WEREN'T WITH ME.
YOU WERE OFF...THINKING
OF SOMETHING ELSE.
THEN WHY DID
YOU STAY AWAY?
BECAUSE YOU
DISAPPROVED OF ME...
JUST AS YOU DO NOW.
OH, PAVEL, YOU HAVE
ALWAYS BEEN LIKE THIS--
SO CORRECT.
AND INSIDE, THE
STRUGGLE NOT TO BE.
GIVE IN TO YOURSELF.
YOU WILL BE HAPPIER.
YOU'LL SEE.
GO TO YOUR FRIENDS.
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
FREE DR. SEVRIN!
GET BACK!
Man: BUT WE WANT
TO SEE HIM NOW!
Protesters: HERBERT! HERBERT!
HERBERT! HERBERT!
Chapel: I THOUGHT
ALL THE ANIMALS
WERE KEPT IN CAGES.
Kirk: WHAT'S
GOING ON, BONES?
TROUBLE.
YOUR FRIEND HERE
DIDN'T WANT A CHECKUP.
TURNS OUT
THERE'S A REASON.
I REFUSE TO ACCEPT
YOUR FINDINGS.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE CHOICE.
THEY'RE THE PRODUCT
OF PREJUDICE,
NOT SCIENCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS MAN
WAS PLANNING ON DOING
ON A PRIMITIVE PLANET,
BUT ASSUMING ONE DID EXIST,
I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
HAD HE SETTLED THERE--
UNTRUE!
THERE WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN
ENOUGH OF THOSE PRIMITIVES
LEFT TO BURY THEIR DEAD.
FANTASY,
FANTASY--
I WISH IT WERE.
A NASTY LITTLE
BUG EVOLVED IN THE
LAST FEW YEARS, JIM.
OUR ASEPTIC, STERILIZED
CIVILIZATION HAS PRODUCED IT--
SYNTHOCOCCUS NOVAE.
IT'S DEADLY.
WE CAN IMMUNIZE AGAINST IT,
BUT WE HAVEN'T LEARNED
TO LICK ALL THE PROBLEMS YET.
DOES HE HAVE IT?
WHAT ABOUT THE OTHERS?
WELL,
THE OTHERS ARE CLEAR.
HE DOESN'T HAVE IT.
HE'S A CARRIER.
REMEMBER YOUR ANCIENT HISTORY?
TYPHOID MARY?
HE'S IMMUNE TO IT,
AS SHE WAS,
BUT HE CARRIES THE DISEASE
AND SPREADS IT TO OTHERS.
IS THE CREW IN DANGER?
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY ALL HAD
FULL-SPECTRUM
IMMUNIZATIONS BEFORE BOARDING.
NOW, MY GUESS IS
THAT HIS FRIENDS HAVE
HAD THEIR SHOTS, TOO.
BUT A REGULAR PROGRAM
OF BOOSTER SHOTS IS NECESSARY.
I'LL HAVE TO CHECK
EVERYONE ON THE SHIP.
THERE COULD BE SOME SKIPS.
IN THE MEANTIME,
HE SHOULD BE PLACED
IN TOTAL ISOLATION.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS.
YOU'RE NOT ISOLATING ME,
YOU'RE IMPRISONING ME.
YOU INVENT THE CRIME,
FIND ME GUILTY,
AND SENTENCE ME.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO RUN THE TEST
YOURSELF, DOCTOR?
YOU KNEW YOU WERE A CARRIER
BEFORE YOU CAME ABOARD,
DIDN'T YOU?
NO!
THEN WHY DID YOU FIGHT
THE EXAMINATION?
IT WAS
AN INFRINGEMENT
ON MY RIGHTS!
PUT HIM IN ISOLATION.
BE READY FOR
THE OBJECTIONS, JIM.
THEY ARE A VOCAL LOT.
YES, I'M READY.
KIRK TO SECURITY.
I WANT A GUARD
MAINTAINED ON DR. SEVRIN
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
BONES, HOW LONG
BEFORE WE KNOW
WHETHER THE CREW
HAS BEEN ENDANGERED
BY THIS INFECTION?
IT'LL SHOW IN 24 HOURS.
IT'S A VIRULENT STRAIN.
Woman: YOU DON'T
BELONG WITH THEM.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE WANT.
YOU WANT IT, TOO!
COME, JOIN US!
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I WANT?
YOU'RE YOUNG.
THINK YOUNG,
BROTHER.
YOU MAKE IT TEMPTING.
Kirk:
MR. SULU.
MR. SULU,
EXPLAIN.
UH...
NO EXPLANATION,
SIR.
Kirk: DR. SEVRIN
WILL BE RELEASED
WHEN WE THINK
HE IS MEDICALLY SAFE.
[PLAYING GUITARLIKE MUSIC]
Man: ♪ STIFF MAN
PUTTING MY MIND IN JAIL ♪
♪ AND THE JUDGE BANGED THE GAVEL
AND SAY, "NO BAIL" ♪
♪ GONNA LICK HIS HAND
AND WAG MY TAIL ♪
All: HERBERT! HERBERT!
HERBERT! HERBERT!
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Scott, on intercom:
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
YES, SCOTTY.
WHAT IS IT?
CAPTAIN, I JUST HAD
TO GIVE ONE OF THOSE
BAREFOOTED WHADDAYACALLEMS
THE BOOT OUT OF HERE.
SHE CAME IN
BOLD AS BRASS,
TRIED TO INCITE MY
CREW TO DISAFFECT.
THANK YOU,
SCOTTY.
MR. SPOCK,
I DON'T SEEM TO BE ABLE
TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THESE PEOPLE.
DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN PERSUADE THEM TO BEHAVE?
I SHALL MAKE
AN ATTEMPT, CAPTAIN.
THANK YOU,
MR. SPOCK.
IF IT WEREN'T FOR
THAT AMBASSADOR'S SON,
THEY'D ALL
BE IN THE BRIG.
YES, SIR.
Kirk, voice-over:
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 5832.5.
THE ARROGANCE OF DR. SEVRIN
AND HIS FOLLOWERS
IS CREATING AN INTOLERABLE
SITUATION ABOARD THE ENTERPRISE.
IF IT CONTINUES,
I'LL BE FORCED TO USE CONTROLS
WHICH MIGHT NOT AGREE
WITH STARFLEET'S SUGGESTION
THAT THEY BE HANDLED
WITH EXTREME TOLERANCE.
I HAVE NO INFLUENCE
OVER WHAT THEY DO.
THEY RESPECT YOU.
THEY WILL LISTEN
TO YOUR REASONING.
FOR THEIR SAKE,
YOU MUST STOP THEM.
DR. SEVRIN, I'M
IN A POSITION TO
HELP YOU AND
YOUR GROUP.
I CAN USE THE
RESOURCES OF
THE ENTERPRISE
TO DETERMINE
WHETHER OR NOT
EDEN ACTUALLY EXISTS
AND TO PLOT ITS
EXACT LOCATION.
I CAN PRESENT A
CASE TO FEDERATION
TO ALLOW YOU AND
YOUR GROUP TO
COLONIZE THAT
PLANET.
NEITHER YOU NOR YOUR PEOPLE
ARE, AT PRESENT,
CHARGED WITH A CRIME.
HOWEVER...
INCITEMENT TO DISAFFECTION...
IS CRIMINAL.
FEDERATION WILL NEVER
ALLOW THE COLONIZATION
OF A PLANET BY CRIMINALS.
IF THEY PERSIST,
THEY WILL BE SO CHARGED
AND FOREVER BARRED
FROM EDEN.
AS I HAVE BEEN BARRED?
THEN YOU KNEW
YOU WERE A CARRIER?
OF COURSE I KNEW!
YOU'VE RESEARCHED
MY LIFE.
YOU'VE READ THE ORDERS
RESTRICTING ME TO TRAVEL
ONLY IN AREAS OF
ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
BECAUSE OF WHAT
MY BODY CARRIES.
WHAT I FAIL TO UNDERSTAND
IS WHY YOU DISOBEY
THOSE ORDERS.
BECAUSE THIS
IS POISON TO ME!
THIS...
STUFF YOU BREATHE,
THIS STUFF YOU LIVE IN...
SHIELDS OF
ARTIFICIAL ATMOSPHERE
THAT WE HAVE LAYERED
ABOUT EVERY PLANET...
THE PROGRAMS
IN THOSE COMPUTERS
THAT RUN YOUR SHIP
AND YOUR LIVES FOR YOU...
THEY BRED WHAT
MY BODY CARRIES.
THAT'S WHAT YOUR
SCIENCE HAVE DONE TO ME.
YOU'VE INFECTED ME!
ONLY THE PRIMITIVES
CAN CLEANSE ME.
I CANNOT PURGE MYSELF
UNTIL I AM AMONG THEM.
ONLY THEIR WAY OF LIVING
IS RIGHT.
I MUST GO TO THEM.
YOUR VERY PRESENCE WILL DESTROY
THE PEOPLE YOU SEEK.
SURELY YOU KNOW THAT.
I SHALL GO TO THEM
AND BE ONE WITH THEM.
AND TOGETHER,
WE SHALL BUILD A WORLD
SUCH AS THIS GALAXY
HAS NEVER SEEN.
A WORLD...
A LIFE...
A LIFE.
SO NOW YOU'RE GOING
TO TRY TO PERSUADE ME
THAT YOUR TECHNOLOGIES
WILL FIND A CURE FOR ME
AND THEN I'LL
BE FREE TO GO.
YES, DOCTOR.
AND FOR THAT REASON,
I SHOULD PERSUADE
MY FRIENDS TO BEHAVE
SO THAT THEY, TOO,
WILL BE ALLOWED?
YES, DOCTOR.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU SEND THEM IN.
I'LL TALK TO THEM.
DR. SEVRIN...
IS INSANE.
I'VE NOT CONSULTED
DR. McCOY,
BUT I HAVE
NO DOUBT OF IT.
I'LL HAVE BONES
CHECK HIM OUT.
SPOCK, I'M SORRY.
YOU HAD GREAT
RESPECT FOR HIM.
BUT IT DOES
EXPLAIN SOME OF
WHAT THEY'VE DONE.
HIS CONDITION DOES NOT
AFFECT MY INTEREST
IN THE MOVEMENT.
THERE IS NO INSANITY
IN WHAT THEY SEEK.
I MADE A PROMISE,
WHICH I SHOULD
LIKE TO KEEP.
WITH YOUR PERMISSION,
I MUST LOCATE EDEN.
I SHALL WORK
IN MY QUARTERS.
MAY I HAVE THE
ASSISTANCE OF MR. CHEKOV
IN AUXILIARY CONTROL?
CERTAINLY.
MR. CHEKOV,
ASSIST MR. SPOCK.
BRIDGE TO SICK BAY.
On intercom:
McCOY HERE.
BONES.
YES, CAPTAIN?
I'D LIKE
TO TALK TO YOU.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5832.6.
I HAVE ASKED DR. McCOY
TO CHECK STARFLEET
MEDICAL RECORDS
TO VERIFY MR. SPOCK'S SUSPICION
THAT DR. SEVRIN IS INSANE.
IN SPITE OF DR. SEVRIN'S
ANTIPATHY TO US,
HE HAS PROMISED MR. SPOCK
THAT HE WILL ORDER HIS DISCIPLES
TO CONFORM TO OUR RULES
AND REGULATIONS.
[DOOR BUZZER]
COME IN.
AM I CROSSING YOU?
NO.
I WAS JUST
THINKING, UH--
HEY, BROTHER,
DO YOU PLAY?
IS IT VULCAN?
CAN I TRY IT?
[PLAYING HARPLIKE MUSIC]
HO HO! THAT'S NOW.
THAT'S REAL NOW.
I REACH THAT, BROTHER.
I REALLY DO.
HERE.
[PLAYING HARPLIKE MUSIC]
HEY, HOW ABOUT A SESSION?
YOU AND US.
IT WOULD SOUND.
THAT'S WHAT I CAME FOR.
I WANTED TO ASK, YOU KNOW,
GREAT WHITE CAPTAIN UPSTAIRS,
BUT HE DON'T REACH US.
BUT WOULD HE SHAKE
ON A SESSION?
I MEAN, WE WANT TO
COOPERATE LIKE YOU ASK,
SO I'M ASKING.
IF I UNDERSTAND YOU
CORRECTLY,
I BELIEVE THE ANSWER
MIGHT BE YES.
I'LL SPREAD THE WORD.
AM I ALLOWED IN?
YES.
I HAVE BEEN LOOKING
FOR YOU, PAVEL.
WHAT ROOM IS THIS?
AUXILIARY CONTROL.
WHAT'S IT FOR?
SHOULD THE MAIN
CONTROL ROOM BREAK DOWN
OR SUFFER DAMAGE,
WE CAN NAVIGATE
THE SHIP FROM HERE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
TO APOLOGIZE.
I SHOULD NOT
HAVE TEASED YOU.
IT WAS CRUEL.
IT DOES NOT MATTER.
OH, BUT IT DOES.
IT IS AGAINST
EVERYTHING I BELIEVE IN.
LET US NOT DISCUSS
YOUR BELIEFS.
AND I DO NOT LIKE
HAVING YOU ANGRY WITH ME...
OR DISAPPROVING.
THEN WHY DO YOU
DO SUCH THINGS?
WHAT ARE YOU
WORKING ON?
I AM ASSISTING MR. SPOCK
IN LOCATING YOUR...EDEN.
OH, NOW YOU ARE
TEASING ME.
I AM NOT.
THESE TAPES
CONTAIN STAR CHARTS.
AND WE PROJECT THE ORBITS
OF THE VARIOUS PLANETS HERE.
UH...BY
A MATHEMATICAL
PROCESS,
WE DETERMINE
WHETHER OR NOT
THEY ARE AFFECTED
BY OTHER BODIES
NOT YET...CHARTED.
DO YOU KNOW
ALL THESE THINGS?
WHAT I DO NOT KNOW,
I FIND OUT FROM
THE COMPUTER BANKS.
IF--
IF I KNEW NOTHING AT ALL,
I COULD NAVIGATE THE SHIP
SIMPLY BY STUDYING
WHAT IS STORED IN THERE.
THEY...CONTAIN THE SUM
OF ALL HUMAN KNOWLEDGE.
THEY...SOLVE OUR
PROBLEMS OF NAVIGATION,
OF CONTROL...
OF LIFE...SUPPORT.
THEY TELL YOU
WHAT TO DO,
AND YOU DO WHAT
THEY TELL YOU?
NO.
WE USE OUR
OWN JUDGMENT ALSO.
I COULD NEVER
OBEY A COMPUTER.
YOU COULD NEVER
LISTEN TO ANYONE.
YOU...ALWAYS HAD...
TO BE DIFFERENT.
NOT DIFFERENT...
WHAT I WANTED TO BE.
THERE IS NOTHING WRONG
IN DOING WHAT YOU WANT.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
Spock, on intercom:
I AM NOT RECEIVING,
MR. CHEKOV.
SPOCK TO CHEKOV,
REPEAT--
I AM NOT RECEIVING.
[PRESSES BUTTON]
I...AM SORRY,
MR. SPOCK.
I WAS...
MOMENTARILY DELAYED.
HIS NAME IS SULU,
SPECIALIST IN WEAPONS
AND NAVIGATION.
HIS HOBBY IS BOTANY.
CAN?
CAN.
I REACH BOTANY.
IT'S MY FAVORITE
OF STUDIES.
WHAT'S YOURS?
VULCAN. SPOCK IS
PRACTICALLY ONE NOW.
EVERYTHING CAN BE HANDLED
FROM AUXILIARY CONTROL.
THE COMPUTERS CONTAIN
ALL THE INFORMATION WE NEED.
WE CAN DO IT!
IT STARTS TO CHIME.
WHEN WILL IT?
SOON.
IT'S LIKE HE SAID NOW.
WE SHOULD ALL GO OUT
AND TRY TO SWING
AS MANY AS POSSIBLE OVER.
DO YOU SUGGEST
ANY SPECIAL WAYS
TO SWING THEM?
JUST BE FRIENDLY.
YOU KNOW HOW
TO BE FRIENDLY.
THEN THEY'LL BE FRIENDLY.
[GUITARLIKE MUSIC PLAYS]
♪ I'M TALKIN'
'BOUT YOU ♪
'BOUT ME ♪
[PLAYING GUITARLIKE MUSIC]
♪ LONG TIME BACK
WHEN THE... ♪
Over intercom:
♪ GALAXY WAS NEW ♪
♪ MAN FOUND OUT
WHAT HE HAD TO DO ♪
♪ FOUND HE HAD TO EAT,
AND HE FOUND HE HAD TO DRINK ♪
♪ AND A LONG TIME LATER,
HE FOUND HE HAD TO THINK ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
♪ YES, THINK ♪
Man: I'M STANDING
HERE WONDERING.
Women: WHAT?
♪ IF A MAN TELLS ANOTHER MAN,
"OUTTA MY WAY" ♪
♪ HE PILES UP TROUBLE
FOR HIMSELF ALL DAY ♪
♪ BUT ALL KINDS OF TROUBLE
COME TO AN END ♪
♪ WHEN A MAN TELLS ANOTHER MAN,
"BE MY FRIEND" ♪
♪ UH-HUH ♪
♪ MY FRIEND ♪
WELL, WHAT'S
IT GOING TO BE?
♪ THERE'S
A MILE-WIDE EMPTINESS ♪
♪ BETWEEN
YOU AND ME ♪
♪ CAN'T REACH ACROSS IT,
HARDLY EVEN SEE ♪
♪ SOMEONE OUGHT
TO TAKE A STEP ♪
♪ ONE WAY OR OTHER ♪
♪ LET'S SAY GOOD-BYE,
OR LET'S SAY BROTHER ♪
All: ♪ BROTHER ♪
♪ BROTHER ♪
♪ HEY, OUT THERE ♪
Women:
♪ I SEE YOU ♪
♪ LET'S GET TOGETHER
AND HAVE SOME FUN ♪
♪ I DON'T KNOW HOW TO DO IT,
BUT IT'S GOT TO BE DONE ♪
[FAST STRUMMING]
[PLAYING STRINGLIKE MUSIC]
[MUSIC PLAYING
OVER INTERCOM]
OHH...
AT LEAST WE KNOW
WHERE THEY ARE AND
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
A YOUNG MIND HAS TO BE
AN UNDISCIPLINED ONE.
THEY'RE TROUBLEMAKERS!
I USED TO GET
INTO A LITTLE TROUBLE
WHEN I WAS THAT AGE,
SCOTTY, DIDN'T YOU?
OHH...
[MUSIC STOPS]
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
[CONSOLES BEEPING]
CAPTAIN, I GET
NO RESPONSE FROM CONTROLS.
WE'RE GOING OFF COURSE.
IT'S SHORTED.
NO...
IT'S CHANNELED
OVER SOMEWHERE.
TO AUXILIARY
CONTROL.
Kirk: BRIDGE TO
AUXILIARY CONTROL.
BRIDGE TO
CAPTAIN, IT SEEMS
AS THOUGH SOMEONE ELSE
IS RUNNING THE SHIP.
Sevrin, on intercom:
THAT'S RIGHT.
SOMEONE ELSE
IS RUNNING THIS SHIP.
I AM.
ALL FUNCTIONS...
LIFE SUPPORT, AS WELL.
YOU CANNOT INTERFERE,
AS I HAVE FROZEN THE DOORS
TO THE CONTROL ROOM.
I DO NOT INTEND
TO HAND OVER THE HELM TO YOU
UNTIL AND UNLESS
WE REACH EDEN.
AND IF I AM IN ANY WAY
PREVENTED FROM REACHING
THAT DESTINATION,
I SHALL DESTROY THIS SHIP
AND ALL ABOARD.
CAN HE DO IT?
Spock: HE HAS
THE CAPABILITY, CAPTAIN.
Scott:
HE'S GOT EVERYTHING
CHANNELED OVER.
START A TRACE-BACK
ON ALL CIRCUITS.
SEE IF YOU CAN
BYPASS THEM.
DO THAT,
AND I SHALL RETALIATE.
I SHALL NOT WARN YOU AGAIN.
CAPTAIN,
WE'RE NOW LEAVING
THE NEUTRAL ZONE,
BEARING INTO
ROMULAN SPACE.
ANY PATROLS?
NEGATIVE.
THERE WILL BE SOON.
DR. SEVRIN...
YOU ARE VIOLATING
ROMULAN SPACE
AND ENDANGERING
THE PEACE OF THE GALAXY.
THE ROMULANS WILL VIEW THIS AS
A MILITARY INTRUSION AND ATTACK.
BRING THE SHIP ABOUT, NOW.
IF YOU BRING HER ABOUT
AND RETURN TO STARBASE,
NO CHARGES WILL BE LEVELED.
LIKE HE SAID,
BROTHER SEVRIN.
IF YOU DO NOT,
YOU WILL NEVER REACH EDEN.
YOU AND THIS SHIP
WILL BE DESTROYED.
Man: HE'S GOT JELLY
IN THE BELLY--REAL SCARED.
HA HA HA.
ADAM...
RAD...
YOU ARE BEING LED
BY A MAN WHO IS INSANE.
YOU ARE BEING USED BY HIM.
HA HA HA.
SPOCK...
YOU TELL THEM.
ADAM, THERE IS
A FILE ON DR. SEVRIN
IN OUR COMPUTER BANKS.
IN IT YOU WILL FIND A REPORT
ATTESTING TO THE FACT
THAT HE IS A CARRIER
OF A BACILLUS STRAIN
KNOWN AS
SYNTHOCOCCUS NOVAE.
HUH!
AIN'T THAT JUST AWFUL.
YOU'LL ALSO FIND A REPORT
FROM THE SAME HOSPITAL,
GIVING A FULL
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROFILE ON HIM
AND PROJECTING
THESE ACTIONS OF HIS.
YEA, BROTHER.
ADAM...
YOU KNOW I REACH YOU.
I BELIEVE
IN WHAT YOU SEEK.
BUT THERE IS
A TRAGIC DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN WHAT YOU WANT
AND WHAT HE WANTS.
YOU'RE MAKING ME CRY.
[PRESSES BUTTON]
THERE IT IS.
THEY'VE ESTABLISHED
EDEN, BROTHER SEVRIN.
Irina: PAVEL
SAID THEY WOULD.
OUR ORIGINAL COURSE
MUST HAVE BEEN
SOMEWHAT IN ERROR.
WHEN WILL WE GET THERE?
Rad: AT THIS
SPEED, 3 HOURS.
THEY'LL TRY TO PERSUADE US
TO CHANGE COURSE PRESENTLY,
AND THEN THEY'LL ATTACK.
HOW DO YOU PLAN
TO STOP THEM?
BY CUTTING OFF
THEIR LIFE SUPPORT?
I HAVE ANOTHER WEAPON.
TAKE CONTROL,
BROTHER RAD.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
MAKING AN ADJUSTMENT
ON THEIR CIRCUITS.
[ADAM PLAYING
GUITARLIKE MUSIC]
♪ HEADIN' OUT TO EDEN ♪
♪ YEA, BROTHER ♪
♪ NO MORE TROUBLE
IN MY BODY OR MY MIND ♪
♪ GONNA LIVE LIKE A KING
ON WHATEVER I FIND ♪
♪ EAT ALL THE FRUIT
AND THROW AWAY THE RIND ♪
♪ YEA, BROTHER ♪
♪ YEA ♪
THEY ARE WITHIN
SENSOR RANGE OF EDEN
AND CONTINUING
TO APPROACH.
WHATEVER THEY'RE GONNA DO,
THEY'RE GONNA DO NOW.
WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
MR. SPOCK, MR. SCOTT.
Adam:
WHEN WILL YOU USE THAT?
AT THE PROPER TIME.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN WE'RE IN ORBIT.
APPROACHING
RIGHT ON THE DOT,
JUST AS THEY PLOTTED
IT, BROTHER SEVRIN.
WHAT WILL THAT
DO TO THEM?
WHAT IS IT?
WELL, I'M USING SOUND
AGAINST THEM--
BEYOND THE ULTRASONIC.
IT WILL STUN THEM
AND ALLOW US TIME TO LEAVE.
WE'LL GO IN ONE
OF THEIR SHUTTLECRAFT.
SOUND PITCHED
THAT HIGH
DOESN'T STUN--
IT DESTROYS.
I REMEMBER
WHEN WE READ IN
THE TEXT THAT IT--
I'VE GONE BEYOND
THOSE TEXTS, IRINA.
IT'S CORRECT FOR YOU
TO BE CONCERNED...
BUT BE ASSURED ALSO.
WE ARE IN ORBIT
OVER EDEN,
BROTHER SEVRIN.
IT DOES DESTROY.
WE CANNOT ALLOW THEM
TO COME AFTER US.
IT WILL NOT
REACH US IN HERE.
I CAN CONTROL IT ALL.
I HAVE ADJUSTED IT SO THAT
IT WILL SUSPEND ITS EFFECTS
AFTER A FEW MOMENTS
AND ALLOW US TIME TO ESCAPE.
THEN, AFTER WE'VE GONE,
IT WILL AUTOMATICALLY
REACTIVATE.
REJOICE, BRETHREN.
SOON WE SHALL STEP
TOGETHER INTO EDEN.
[PHASER FIRING]
[SILENCE]
SPOCK.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, SPOCK.
IT STOPPED.
NO, CAPTAIN,
IT HASN'T STOPPED.
IT HAS GONE BEYOND--
CAPTAIN,
THEY'RE USING--
Adam: ♪ STEPPIN'
INTO EDEN ♪
Adam, women:
♪ YEA, BROTHER ♪
♪ STEPPIN'
INTO EDEN ♪
♪ YEA, BROTHER ♪
♪ NO MORE TROUBLE
IN MY BODY OR MY MIND ♪
♪ GONNA LIVE LIKE A KING
ON WHATEVER I FIND ♪
♪ EAT ALL THE FRUIT
AND THROW AWAY THE RIND ♪
♪ YEA, BROTHER ♪
NOW WE MAY LEAVE.
AGH.
CAPTAIN, GO.
YOU MUST...
DESTROY THE--
WHAT IS IT?
ULTRASONICS.
THE PANEL.
KIRK TO ENGINEERING.
BRIDGE.
HANGAR DECK.
KIRK TO TRANSPORTER ROOM.
KIRK TO BRIDGE.
DO YOU READ ME?
COME IN.
On intercom:
SULU HERE, CAPTAIN.
WHAT HAPPENED TO US?
I HEARD A WHISTLE,
AND THEN--
NEVER MIND.
DO WE HAVE CONTROL OF THE SHIP?
Chekov,
on intercom:
NO, SIR.
CONTROL
IS IN AUXILIARY.
CAN WE BREAK OUT OF
ORBIT IF WE HAVE TO?
I THINK SO, SIR.
Man, on intercom:
HANGAR DECK
TO CAPTAIN.
KIRK HERE.
SIR, ONE OF THE
SHUTTLECRAFTS
HAS BEEN TAKEN.
WE WERE ALL
KNOCKED OUT.
STAND BY.
DO YOU READ ANY ROMULANS?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, I AM PICKING UP
THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
WHERE?
IT HAS LANDED.
EXCEPT FOR THOSE
ABOARD THE CRAFT,
I READ NO LIFE AT ALL,
NEITHER HUMANOID
NOR ANIMAL.
AUXILIARY CONTROL
TO DR. McCOY.
BONES, ARE
YOU ALL RIGHT?
McCoy, on intercom:
YES, JIM.
STAND BY, TRANSPORTER ROOM.
FULL MEDICAL GEAR.
Chekov, on intercom:
BRIDGE TO CAPTAIN KIRK.
DO YOU WISH TO OPEN
COMMUNICATIONS, SIR?
NO. NO.
THEY TRIED TO DESTROY US.
LET THEM THINK
THEY SUCCEEDED.
I WANT THE COORDINATES
ZEROED IN
SO THAT WHEN WE BEAM DOWN,
WE WON'T BE VISIBLE TO THEM.
SCOTTY, YOU
HAVE THE CON.
IF ANY ROMULANS APPEAR,
TRY TO MAKE THEM UNDERSTAND.
I DO NOT WANT
TO PROVOKE COMBAT.
MR. SPOCK...
MR. CHEKOV, JOIN US
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
[TRICORDER HUMMING]
THE LEGENDS
WERE TRUE, CAPTAIN.
A FANTASTICALLY
BEAUTIFUL PLANET.
Chekov: EDEN.
IS THIS WHAT THEY
BELIEVED THEY'D FIND?
THEN I CAN UNDERSTAND.
[TRICORDER STOPS HUMMING]
[COMMUNICATOR OPENS]
SPREAD OUT.
APPROACH WITH CAUTION.
DR. SEVRIN.
AAH!
WHAT IS IT?
THE FLOWER, SIR.
I TOUCHED IT.
IT'S LIKE FIRE.
IT'S BURNED.
ALL THIS PLANT LIFE
IS FULL OF ACID.
EVEN THE GRASS, JIM.
WILL OUR CLOTHING
PROTECT US?
IT SHOULD,
FOR A WHILE.
Spock:
CAPTAIN.
BONES?
POISON.
THE FRUIT IS DEADLY.
HIS NAME WAS ADAM.
Kirk:
THERE'S THE SHUTTLECRAFT.
[IRINA GASPING]
HERE.
WE'LL HELP YOU.
OH! AH!
DR. SEVRIN--
BONES!
McCoy: HE SHOULD BE
BEAMED ABOARD, JIM.
HE NEEDS MORE
THAN I CAN DO FOR HIM HERE.
SPOCK
TO ENTERPRISE.
Scott, on communicator:
ENTERPRISE HERE.
STAND BY TO BEAM ABOARD
INJURED PARTIES.
A MEDICAL TEAM
TO THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
NO...NO,
WE'RE NOT LEAVING.
WE CAN HELP YOU
ABOARD THE SHIP.
WE'RE NOT
LEAVING EDEN.
NONE OF US.
BE SENSIBLE, DOCTOR.
WE'RE NOT LEAVING.
McCoy: COME BACK
HERE, YOU FOOL!
Kirk: SEVRIN, DON'T!
YOU'LL KILL YOURSELF!
McCoy:
DON'T BITE INTO THAT!
Kirk: STOP!
IT WAS
SO BEAUTIFUL!
Lieutenant Palmer: I HAVE
STARBASE NOW, CAPTAIN.
Kirk: ALERT THEM
THAT WE HAVE THE FOUR
AND WE'RE READY
TO BEAM THEM DOWN,
AND MARK THE
INCIDENT CLOSED.
AYE, SIR.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER.
SCOTTY, ARE THEY THERE?
Scott, on intercom:
THREE OF THEM, SIR.
EXPECTING A
FOURTH ANY MINUTE.
STAND BY.
MR. CHEKOV...
DO YOU WISH TO ATTEND?
CAPTAIN, I WISH
FIRST TO APOLOGIZE
FOR MY CONDUCT
DURING THIS TIME.
I DID NOT MAINTAIN MYSELF
UNDER PROPER DISCIPLINE.
I ENDANGERED THE SHIP
AND ITS PERSONNEL BY MY CONDUCT.
I RESPECTFULLY SUBMIT MYSELF
FOR DISCIPLINARY ACTION.
THANK YOU,
MR. CHEKOV.
YOU DID WHAT
YOU HAD TO DO,
AS DID WE ALL.
EVEN YOUR FRIENDS.
YOU MAY GO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I WAS COMING
TO SAY GOODBYE.
AND I WAS COMING
TO SAY GOODBYE TO YOU.
BE INCORRECT...
OCCASIONALLY.
AND YOU BE CORRECT.
Spock:
MISS GALLIULIN.
IT IS MY SINCERE WISH
THAT YOU DO NOT GIVE UP
YOUR SEARCH FOR EDEN.
I HAVE NO DOUBT
BUT THAT YOU WILL
FIND IT--
OR MAKE IT
YOURSELVES.
THANK YOU.
WE...REACH,
MR. SPOCK.