Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5818.4--
A BOTANICAL PLAGUE
IS DEVASTATING A PLANET
IN THE QUADRANT
OF THE GALAXY
WHERE THE ENTERPRISE
IS OPERATING AT PRESENT.
IT THREATENS TO DESTROY
THE VEGETATION
ON THE ENTIRE PLANET,
LEAVING IT UNINHABITABLE.
UNDER FEDERATION ORDERS,
WE'RE PROCEEDING
AT TOP WARP SPEED
TO THE PLANET ARDANA,
WHERE THE ONLY
KNOWN SOURCE
OF ZIENITE EXISTS.
IT IS THE ONE SUBSTANCE
THAT CAN HALT
THE PLAGUE.
CAPTAIN, THE HIGH ADVISER
OF ARDANA
IS READY TO RECEIVE YOU
ON STRATOS, SIR.
ON STRATOS?
THAT'S THEIR CLOUD CITY,
ISN'T IT, MR. SPOCK?
IT IS, CAPTAIN.
THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE.
DO YOU HAVE
THE COORDINATES
TO THE MINE
ENTRANCE AVAILABLE?
THEY'VE ALREADY BEEN
PROVIDED TO THE TRANSPORT
OFFICER, CAPTAIN,
ALONG WITH THOSE
OF THE COUNCIL CHAMBER
OF THE HIGH ADVISER.
KIRK TO
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
Scotty: READY
TO TRANSPORT, CAPTAIN.
MR. SCOTT,
ARE YOU LOCKED IN
ON THE MINE ENTRANCE
OR ON THEIR
CLOUD CITY, STRATOS?
THE MINE ENTRANCE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU
ORDERED, CAPTAIN.
FINE.
UHURA, TELL
THE HIGH ADVISER
THAT, UH, WE REQUEST
TO DISPENSE
WITH THE WELCOMING
CEREMONIES,
DUE TO
THE EMERGENCY,
THAT WE'RE BEAMING
DIRECTLY DOWN
TO THE MINE ENTRANCE
IN ORDER TO
ENSURE THE FASTEST
POSSIBLE DELIVERY
OF THE ZIENITE.
THE NEED IS URGENT.
AYE, SIR.
MR. SPOCK,
COME WITH ME.
OH, AND TELL THEM
THAT WE APPRECIATE
THE HONOR
AND THAT WE LOOK
FORWARD TO SOME
VISIT IN THE FUTURE.
AYE, SIR.
STRATOS, CAPTAIN...
A CITY ACTUALLY FLOATING
IN THE SKY.
LOOKS AS TRANQUIL
AS ITS REPUTATION,
DOESN'T IT?
IT IS ONE OF THE MOST
INTERESTING METROPOLISES
IN THE GALAXY.
HAVE YOU EVER
VISITED HERE, CAPTAIN?
ONCE. I DIDN'T HAVE
TIME TO LOOK AROUND.
I'VE NEVER HAD
THE OPPORTUNITY.
HOWEVER, I HEAR
ITS ART FORMS
ARE INCOMPARABLE.
YES. ART IS
THE POPULATION'S
CHIEF OCCUPATION.
IT IS A TOTALLY
INTELLECTUAL SOCIETY.
ALL FORMS OF VIOLENCE
HAVE BEEN ELIMINATED.
THERE'S
THE MINE ENTRANCE.
THE ZIENITE CONSIGNMENT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN THERE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
THOSE TROGLYTE MINERS
WERE SUPPOSED TO HAVE
MADE DELIVERY
WHEN WE BEAMED DOWN.
PERHAPS THERE IS
ANOTHER ENTRANCE, CAPTAIN.
PERHAPS.
IT WOULD SEEM THE TROGLYTES
HAVE CHANGED THEIR MINDS
ABOUT DELIVERY.
Kirk: SPACE--
THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP ENTERPRISE.
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE STRANGE NEW WORLDS,
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS,
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
WHO ARE YOU?
WHAT'S THE MEANING
OF THIS ATTACK?
INTERFERENCE BREEDS
ATTACK, CAPTAIN.
COME ON!
WE'RE HERE BY PERMISSION
OF YOUR GOVERNMENT COUNCIL
ON AN EMERGENCY MISSION.
MOVE ON, CAPTAIN.
TROGLYTES, HALT!
SURRENDER
OR WE'LL FIRE!
ARE YOU HARMED,
GENTLEMEN?
NO. JUST A LITTLE
SHAKEN UP.
I'M PLASUS, HIGH ADVISER
OF THE PLANET COUNCIL.
CAPTAIN KIRK,
ENTERPRISE.
MY FIRST OFFICER
MR. SPOCK.
GREETINGS,
MR. ADVISER.
MY REGRETS FOR
THE UNPLEASANTNESS OF
YOUR WELCOME TO ARDANA.
IT WAS RATHER WARM.
UNFORTUNATELY,
VIOLENCE IS HABITUAL
WITH THE TROGLYTES,
BUT I ASSURE YOU,
THIS INSULT WILL NOT
GO UNPUNISHED.
WELL, I'M MORE CONCERNED
WITH THE ZIENITE CONSIGNMENT.
WHY WASN'T IT IN
ITS SPECIFIED LOCATION?
APPARENTLY,
THE DISRUPTERS
HAVE CONFISCATED IT,
JUST AS I KNEW
THEY WOULD.
THE DISRUPTERS--
WHO ARE THEY?
A SMALL GROUP OF
TROGLYTE MALCONTENTS.
ALL THE OTHER TROGLYTES
ARE COMPLETELY
DOMINATED BY THEM.
IT'S THE DISRUPTERS
WHO ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THEIR REFUSAL
TO CONTINUE MINING
FOR ZIENITE.
THEY AGREED
TO THE DELIVERY.
YOUR COUNCIL
ASSURED US OF IT.
THEY AGREED,
OBVIOUSLY,
AS A RUSE TO GET
VALUABLE HOSTAGES.
HOSTAGES?
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
TO FORCE THE COUNCIL
TO MEET THEIR DEMANDS.
ORGANIZE
A SEARCH PARTY
IMMEDIATELY
AND FIND THE ZIENITE
CONSIGNMENT.
MEANWHILE, CAPTAIN,
I WOULD SUGGEST
THAT YOU AND
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
BE OUR GUESTS
ON STRATOS.
VERY WELL.
I...DO HOPE THE SEARCH
WILL BE BRIEF, MR. ADVISER.
WE'LL DO
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE
TO MAKE IT SO.
COME, GENTLEMEN.
REMARKABLE.
THE FINEST EXAMPLE
OF SUSTAINED
ANTIGRAVITY ELEVATION
I'VE EVER SEEN.
THE SENTINEL TOLD ME
OF OUR HONORED
GUESTS, MY FATHER.
I CAME TO EXTEND
GREETINGS.
A MOST GRACIOUS ACT.
GENTLEMEN,
ONE OF OUR PLANET'S
MOST INCOMPARABLE
WORKS OF ART--
MY DAUGHTER DROXINE.
CAPTAIN JAMES KIRK.
A PLEASURE, MADAM.
INDEED, YES,
CAPTAIN.
AND FIRST OFFICER
SPOCK.
I HAVE NEVER BEFORE
MET A VULCAN, SIR.
NOR I A WORK
OF ART, MADAM.
COME GENTLEMEN THERE IS MUCH TO
SEE IN OUR CITY.
THIS IS OUR
COUNCIL GALLERY.
IT IS OPEN TO ALL
CITY DWELLERS.
WE HAVE
SOME OF THE FINEST
OF OUR VARIOUS ART FORMS
ASSEMBLED HERE
FOR THE VIEWING
AND CONTEMPLATION OF EVERY--
DISRUPTERS AGAIN!
HOW DREADFUL.
THEY'RE DESPOILING
THE WHOLE CITY.
DESPOIL?
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
BY KEEPING US
IN CONSTANT TURMOIL,
THEY HOPE TO FORCE
THE COUNCIL TO ACCEDE
TO THEIR DEMANDS.
WHAT ARE THEIR DEMANDS?
COMPLETELY
UNREASONABLE,
CAPTAIN,
BUT NOTHING YOU NEED
BE CONCERNED WITH.
I MUST CONCERN MYSELF WITH IT
IF IT SHOULD INTERFERE
WITH THE DELIVERY
OF ZIENITE TO MERAK II.
MR. ADVISER,
THE PLANT LIFE IS
THE SOURCE OF OXYGEN
ON THAT PLANET.
OBVIOUSLY, IF ALL
PLANT LIFE IS DESTROYED,
THE HUMANOID LIFE
WILL FOLLOW.
I ASSURE YOU GENTLEMEN
YOU WILL GET
WHAT YOU CAME FOR.
I HOPE SO.
ARDANA IS A MEMBER
OF THE FEDERATION,
AND IT IS YOUR COUNCIL'S
RESPONSIBILITY
THAT NOTHING INTERFERES
WITH ITS OBLIGATION
TO ANOTHER MEMBER
OF THE FEDERATION.
OF COURSE, AND WE ACCEPT
THE RESPONSIBILITY.
WHY DO THEY DESTROY
ART FORMS?
THAT IS A LOSS
TO EVERYONE.
ART MEANS NOTHING
TO THE DISRUPTERS.
THIS IS THE ONLY FORM
THEY UNDERSTAND.
THE DISTURBANCES
ACCOMPANYING
YOUR ARRIVAL
HAVE BEEN MOST
WEARYING.
NO DOUBT
YOU WOULD LIKE
TO REST.
THAT WOULD BE
MOST WELCOME,
MR. ADVISER.
CHAMBERS HAVE
BEEN PREPARED
FOR YOU.
A SENTINEL
WILL GUIDE YOU
TO THEM.
I'M SORRY THEY WERE
SO POORLY TREATED
ON THEIR FIRST VISIT
TO OUR PLANET.
IT'S FORTUNATE THAT
THEY WERE NOT
SERIOUSLY HURT.
OH, YES, THAT
WOULD HAVE BEEN DREADFUL.
FURTHER VIOLENCE
COULD CREATE
GRAVE DIFFICULTIES
BETWEEN ARDANA
AND THE FEDERATION.
THE DISRUPTERS MUST BE MAD
TO ATTACK TWO SUCH
CHARMING STRANGERS.
THEY GROW MORE DARING
AND DETERMINED
EVERY DAY.
NOW THEY SEEK TO FIND
ALLIES IN THE GALAXY.
DO YOU THINK THAT
CAPTAIN KIRK AND HIS
VERY ATTRACTIVE OFFICER
WILL FEEL THAT
WE ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THEIR INJURIES?
ALL THIS TIME,
I THOUGHT
YOU WERE WORRIED
ABOUT OUR DIPLOMATIC
RELATIONS.
APOLOGIES,
MR. ADVISER,
BUT THIS TROGLYTE
WAS APPREHENDED
LEAVING THE CITY.
HE IS WITHOUT
A TRANSPORT CARD,
SO WE THOUGHT
YOU WOULD WANT TO
QUESTION HIM.
REMOVE HIS SHIELDS.
WHAT IS YOUR BUSINESS
IN STRATOS, TROGLYTE?
SPEAK!
I COMMAND YOU.
MY BUSINESS
IS TO REPAIR.
REPAIR WHAT?
THEY ARE DAMAGE TENSIONS PATH.
INDEED?
THEN YOU MUST HAVE
A REPAIR PERMIT.
WHERE IS IT?
IT WAS FORGOTTEN.
DID YOU ALSO FORGET
YOUR TRANSPORT CARD?
IT WAS LOST
WHEN YOUR SENTINELS
ATTACKED ME.
AND WHERE WAS
YOUR CAVERN
IMPLEMENT LOST?
COULD THIS PERHAPS
BE IT?!
I CAME TO MAKE REPAIRS.
AND YOU SHALL
MAKE THEM,
BY GIVING US
THE NAMES
OF THE DISRUPTERS.
I KNOW NOTHING.
I WOULD ADVISE YOU
TO INCREASE
YOUR KNOWLEDGE.
THAT IS NOT POSSIBLE
FOR A TROGLYTE.
THE STRATOS CITY DWELLERS
HAVE SAID IT.
SECURE HIM
TO THE ROSTRUM.
AAAH!
HOW UNFORTUNATE.
Spock, voice-over:
THIS TROUBLED PLANET
IS A PLACE
OF THE MOST VIOLENT CONTRASTS.
THOSE WHO RECEIVE THE REWARDS
ARE TOTALLY SEPARATED
FROM THOSE WHO SHOULDER
THE BURDENS.
IT IS NOT A WISE LEADERSHIP.
HERE ON STRATOS,
EVERYTHING IS INCOMPARABLY
BEAUTIFUL AND PLEASANT.
THE HIGH ADVISER'S
CHARMING DAUGHTER DROXINE...
PARTICULARLY SO.
THE NAME DROXINE SEEMS
APPROPRIATE FOR HER.
I WONDER--CAN SHE RETAIN
SUCH PURITY
AND SWEETNESS OF MIND
AND BE AWARE OF THE LIFE
OF THE PEOPLE
ON THE SURFACE
OF THE PLANET?
THERE, THE HARSH LIFE
IN THE MINES
IS INSTILLING THE PEOPLE
WITH A BITTER HATRED.
THE YOUNG GIRL WHO LED
THE ATTACK AGAINST US
WHEN WE BEAMED DOWN
WAS FILLED WITH THE VIOLENCE
OF DESPERATION.
IF THE LOVELY DROXINE KNEW
OF THE YOUNG MINER'S MISERY,
I WONDER HOW THE KNOWLEDGE
WOULD AFFECT HER.
MR. SPOCK.
I THOUGHT YOU HAD
ACCOMPANIED CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THE REST CHAMBER.
YOUR MOVEMENTS
AWAKENED ME.
OH, MY APOLOGIES.
I DID NOT REALIZE
THEY WOULD DISTURB YOU.
ONLY VULCAN EARS
WOULD FIND THE NOISE
DISCERNIBLE.
IT SEEMS THAT VULCANS
ARE FASCINATINGLY DIFFERENT...
IN MANY WAYS.
THE SAME MAY BE SAID
OF STRATOS INHABITANTS.
VULCAN EYES
ARE VERY DISCERNING, TOO.
I HEAR THAT
INTELLECTUALLY,
VULCANS ARE
AS HIGHLY EVOLVED
AS STRATOS CITY
DWELLERS.
WE DO...
PRIDE OURSELVES
ON OUR LOGIC.
YOU AGAIN.
YOU SLEEP LIGHTLY,
CAPTAIN.
YES. DUTY
IS A GOOD TEACHER.
I SEE YOU'VE CHANGED
YOUR DRESSMAKER.
RELEASE ME!
SO YOU CAN ATTACK ME AGAIN?
THAT WOULD BE FOOLISH.
CALL THE GUARDS
IF YOU'RE AFRAID,
CAPTAIN.
I'M NOT AFRAID.
IN FACT, I FIND THIS
RATHER ENJOYABLE.
I DO NOT!
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL MAKE A DEAL WITH YOU.
YOU ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS,
AND I'LL LET YOU UP.
WHAT QUESTIONS?
YOUR WORD FIRST.
I WILL ANSWER.
YOU ONLY TAKE A MATE
ONCE EVERY 7 YEARS?
THE 7-YEAR CYCLE
IS BIOLOGICALLY INHERENT
IN ALL VULCANS.
AT THAT TIME,
THE MATING DRIVE
OUTWEIGHS ALL
OTHER MOTIVATIONS.
AND IS THERE NOTHING
THAT CAN DISTURB
THAT CYCLE,
MR. SPOCK?
EXTREME FEMININE BEAUTY
IS ALWAYS...
DISTURBING...
MADAM.
Kirk: SPOCK?
I DID NOT COME HERE
TO KILL YOU, CAPTAIN.
THEN WHY THIS?
TO TAKE YOU HOSTAGE.
AM I...INTRUDING, CAPTAIN?
VANNA.
DROXINE.
WHY HAVE YOU
COME HERE?
TO WELCOME
OUR HONORED GUESTS,
AS I WAS TAUGHT
TO DO WHEN I SERVED
IN YOUR FATHER'S
HOUSEHOLD.
HAS SHE INJURED YOU,
CAPTAIN?
OH, NO, NOT AT ALL.
IN FACT, HER VISIT
WAS QUITE ENLIGHTENING.
OH?
YES. IT SEEMS
THE TROGLYTES
ARE UNDER
THE IMPRESSION
THAT THE ENTERPRISE
IS HERE
TO INTIMIDATE THEM.
SEND A SENTINEL
TO THE REST CHAMBER
IMMEDIATELY.
IT IS NOT IMPRESSION,
CAPTAIN.
IT IS THE TRUTH.
WE'RE HERE TO GET
THAT ZIENITE CONSIGNMENT,
AND THAT'S IT.
STARSHIPS DO NOT
TRANSPORT CARGO.
IN TIMES OF EMERGENCY,
THEY DO ANYTHING,
AND BELIEVE ME,
THIS BOTANICAL PLAGUE
IS AN EMERGENCY.
LIES WILL NOT KEEP
THE TROGLYTES
IN THE CAVERNS,
AND NEITHER WILL
YOUR STARSHIP.
YOU TALK LIKE
A DISRUPTER, VANNA.
I SPEAK
FOR MY PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE AS MUCH
RIGHT TO THE CLOUDS
AS THE STRATOS
DWELLERS.
THE STRATOS IS FOR
ADVISERS AND STUDIERS.
WHAT WOULD TROGLYTES
DO HERE?
LIVE...
IN THE SUNLIGHT
AND WARMTH,
AS EVERYONE SHOULD.
THE CAVERNS ARE WARM,
AND YOUR EYES
ARE NOT ACCUSTOMED
TO LIGHT,
JUST AS YOUR MINDS
ARE NOT ACCUSTOMED
TO LOGIC.
UNACCUSTOMED
TO LIGHT AND WARMTH?
THAT'S NECESSARY
TO ALL HUMANOIDS.
SURELY YOU DON'T DENY IT
TO THE TROGLYTES.
THE TROGLYTES
ARE WORKERS, CAPTAIN.
OH, SURELY YOU MUST BE
AWARE OF THAT.
THEY MINE ZIENITE
FOR SHIPMENT,
TILL THE SOIL.
THOSE THINGS
CANNOT BE DONE HERE.
IN OTHER WORDS,
THEY PERFORM
ALL THE PHYSICAL TOIL
NECESSARY TO
MAINTAIN STRATOS.
THAT IS THEIR FUNCTION
IN OUR SOCIETY.
BUT THEY ARE NOT ALLOWED
TO SHARE ITS ADVANTAGES.
HOW CAN THEY SHARE
WHAT THEY DO NOT UNDERSTAND?
THEY CAN BE TAUGHT
TO UNDERSTAND,
ESPECIALLY IN A SOCIETY
THAT PRIDES ITSELF
IN ENLIGHTENMENT.
THE COMPLETE SEPARATION
OF TOIL AND LEISURE
HAS GIVEN ARDANA
THIS PERFECTLY BALANCED
SOCIAL SYSTEM, CAPTAIN.
WHY SHOULD WE CHANGE IT?
THE SURFACE OF THE PLANET
IS ALMOST UNENDURABLE.
TO RESTRICT A SEGMENT
OF THE POPULATION
TO SUCH HARDSHIP
IS UNTHINKABLE
IN AN EVOLVED CULTURE.
THE SURFACE IS MARRED
BY VIOLENCE,
LIKE THE TROGLYTES.
HERE ON STRATOS,
WE HAVE COMPLETELY
ELIMINATED VIOLENCE.
YOU STILL REFUSE
TO DISCLOSE THE NAMES
OF THE OTHER DISRUPTERS?
THERE ARE
NO DISRUPTERS.
VERY WELL,
IF YOU PREFER THE RAYS.
TROGLYTE
IS AN ABBREVIATION
OF AN ANCIENT
EARTH TERM, CAPTAIN.
ITS TECHNICAL
TRANSLATION IS
"CAVE DWELLER."
YES. I SHOULD HAVE
REALIZED.
AAH!
MR. ADVISER.
YOU SAID YOU WERE
GOING TO QUESTION VANNA,
NOT TORTURE HER.
SHE'S STUBBORN.
AND AS YOU YOURSELF
POINTED OUT, CAPTAIN,
THE SEARCH FOR
YOUR ZIENITE CONSIGNMENT
MUST BE SHORT.
SURELY THERE ARE
BETTER METHODS THAN THIS.
PHYSICAL DISCOMFORT
IS EXTREMELY
PERSUASIVE, CAPTAIN.
YES. BUT I WON'T STAND BY
WHILE SOMEONE IS TORTURED.
IS IT PREFERABLE
TO SPARE VANNA
AND ALLOW
AN ENTIRE PLANET
TO BE DESTROYED?
VIOLENCE IN REALITY
IS QUITE DIFFERENT
FROM THEORY,
IS IT NOT, MADAM?
BUT WHAT ELSE
CAN THEY UNDERSTAND,
MR. SPOCK?
ALL THE LITTLE THINGS
YOU AND I UNDERSTAND
AND EXPECT FROM LIFE,
SUCH AS EQUALITY,
KINDNESS, JUSTICE.
TROGLYTES ARE NOT
LIKE STRATOS DWELLERS,
MR. SPOCK.
THEY'RE A CONGLOMERATE
OF INFERIOR SPECIES.
THE ABSTRACT CONCEPTS
OF AN INTELLECTUAL
SOCIETY
ARE BEYOND
THEIR COMPREHENSION.
THE ABSTRACT CONCEPTS
OF LOYALTY AND LEADERSHIP
SEEM PERFECTLY CLEAR
TO VANNA.
A FEW TROGLYTES
ARE BROUGHT HERE
AS RETAINERS.
VANNA WAS ONE OF THEM,
AS ARE THE SENTINELS.
THEY'VE RECEIVED
MORE TRAINING
THAN THE OTHERS.
BUT OBVIOUSLY
NO MORE CONSIDERATION.
I FAIL TO SEE
THE PURPOSE
OF THIS CONTINUED
CRITICISM.
THE ONLY WAY YOU'LL USE
THAT DEVICE AGAIN
IS ON ONE OF US.
AN IMPOSING DISPLAY
OF PRIMITIVE GALLANTRY,
GENTLEMEN.
YOU REALIZE, OF COURSE,
THAT THE SENTINELS
COULD REMOVE YOU.
OF COURSE.
BUT STARFLEET COMMAND
WON'T TAKE KINDLY
TO HAVING EITHER RAYS
OR PHYSICAL FORCE USED
AGAINST ONE OF ITS
COMMAND PERSONNEL,
MR. ADVISER.
WHY ARE YOU SO CONCERNED
WITH THIS DISRUPTER'S
WELL-BEING?
BEYOND PLAIN
HUMANITARIANISM,
MY ORDERS ARE TO GET
THAT ZIENITE.
THEN STOP INTERFERING,
AND I'LL GET IT FOR YOU.
YOU WON'T GET IT
THROUGH TORTURE!
WE WILL GET IT FOR YOU
AND IN OUR OWN WAY.
REMOVE THE PRISONER
TO CONFINEMENT QUARTERS.
YOU WILL RETURN
TO YOUR SHIP AT ONCE...
OR I SHALL CONTACT YOUR
STARFLEET COMMAND MYSELF.
AND REPORT
YOUR INTERFERENCE
WITH THIS PLANET'S
GOVERNMENT.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
Scotty: ENTERPRISE,
CAPTAIN.
MR. SCOTT, WE'RE
READY TO BEAM UP.
AYE, SIR.
IF CAPTAIN KIRK
APPEARS AGAIN...
KILL HIM.
Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5819.0.
MORE THAN 8 HOURS
HAVE PASSED
SINCE THE CONSIGNMENT
OF ZIENITE DISAPPEARED,
AND WE HAVE STILL FOUND
NO TRACE OF IT.
WE'VE RECEIVED WORD
FROM MERAK II
THAT THE BOTANICAL PLAGUE
IS SPREADING RAPIDLY.
DELIVERY OF THE ZIENITE
IS IMPERATIVE WITHIN 12 HOURS,
OR ALL LIFE ON THE PLANET
WILL BE ANNIHILATED.
LIEUTENANT UHURA,
ADVISE STARFLEET COMMAND
THAT THE ZIENITE
HAS NOT BEEN DELIVERED.
IN MY OPINION, PLASUS' METHOD
OF ACCOMPLISHING DELIVERY
WILL NOT SUCCEED.
IF THE ZIENITE IS NOT
DELIVERED SHORTLY,
I SHALL HAVE TO
VIOLATE PLASUS' ORDER
OF NON-INTERFERENCE
AND WIN THE CONFIDENCE
OF THE TROGLYTE LEADER
WITH THE USE OF REASON.
THAT MAY NOT
BE EASY, JIM.
MEDICAL ANALYSIS
INDICATES
THAT TROGLYTES ARE
MENTALLY INFERIOR.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE, BONES.
THE TROGLYTES HAVE ACCEPTED
PERSONAL SACRIFICE,
A COMMON CAUSE.
MENTALLY INFERIOR BEINGS
ARE INCAPABLE OF THAT.
LOOK. I'VE CHECKED
MY FINDINGS THOROUGHLY.
THEIR INTELLECT RATINGS
ARE ALMOST 20% BELOW
AVERAGE.
THEY'RE ALL
THE SAME SPECIES.
THOSE WHO LIVE ON STRATOS
AND THOSE WHO LIVE BELOW
ALL ORIGINATED
ON THE PLANET.
THEIR PHYSICAL AND MENTAL
EVOLUTION MUST BE SIMILAR.
THAT IS BASIC BIOLOGICAL LAW.
THAT'S TRUE, SPOCK,
BUT OBVIOUSLY,
THE ANCESTORS
OF THOSE WHO LIVE
ON STRATOS
REMOVED THEMSELVES
FROM THE ENVIRONMENT
OF THE MINES.
THEREFORE, THEY
AVOIDED THE EFFECTS
OF CERTAIN NATURAL
GROWTHS.
NATURAL GROWTHS?
WHAT KIND?
I HAD THIS ZIENITE
SAMPLE SENT UP
FROM THE SURFACE.
NOW, UNSEALED,
IT WOULD HAVE HAD
DETRIMENTAL EFFECTS
ON EVERYBODY HERE.
INCREDIBLE.
ZIENITE IS SHIPPED
ALL OVER THE GALAXY--
WHEREVER THERE IS DANGER
OF PLANT BACTERIA.
NO SIDE EFFECTS
HAVE EVER BEEN REPORTED.
THERE ARE NONE
AFTER IT'S REFINED.
BUT IN ITS RAW STATE,
IT EMITS AN ODORLESS,
INVISIBLE GAS
THAT RETARDS
THE INTELLECTUAL
FUNCTIONING
OF THE MIND
AND HEIGHTENS
THE EMOTION.
THEREFORE, IT RELEASES
A VIOLENT REACTION.
AND THE MINES
ARE FULL OF THAT GAS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THE TROGLYTES
ARE CONSTANTLY
EXPOSED TO IT.
BONES. THE DISRUPTERS,
VANNA--
IT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE.
THEY'VE OUTWITTED
A HIGHLY ORGANIZED,
SCIENTIFIC CULTURE
FOR MONTHS.
AS PART OF THE STAFF
OF STRATOS,
VANNA WAS REMOVED
FROM EXPOSURE
FOR A LONG PERIOD.
IT IS LIKELY THAT
WITHOUT SUCH EXPOSURE,
THE EFFECT SLOWLY
WEARS OFF.
THAT'S RIGHT, SPOCK,
AND THE OTHER
DISRUPTERS
WERE PROBABLY
REMOVED FROM
THE EXPOSURE, TOO.
DOES THE BRAIN
RETURN TO NORMAL?
ACCORDING TO
FINDINGS, IT SHOULD.
CAN YOU NEUTRALIZE
THE GAS?
NO, BUT A FILTER
MASK SHOULD REMOVE
THE EXPOSURE.
FIND ONE. MEET US
IN THE TRANSPORTER ROOM.
THIS MASK
AUTOMATICALLY ELIMINATES
ALL SUBSTANCES
INJURIOUS TO HUMANOID
LIFE, CHEMICAL AS WELL
AS BACTERIAL.
WE HAVE USED
THESE FILTER MASKS
FREQUENTLY ON--
AND DO YOU REALLY
EXPECT ME TO BELIEVE
THAT THAT MASK CAN ACHIEVE
INTELLECTUAL EQUALITY
FOR THE TROGLYTES?
THERE'S EVERY
INDICATION
THAT THE EFFECT
OF THE GAS
IS TEMPORARY,
EVEN AFTER
REPEATED EXPOSURE.
HOW CAN A MERE FILTER
ACCOMPLISH
WHAT CENTURIES OF EVOLUTION
HAVE FAILED TO DO?
DR. McCOY HAS ANALYZED
THE ZIENITE THOROUGHLY.
WE'VE CHECKED HIS FINDINGS
THROUGH THE COMPUTER,
AND THEY'RE
ABSOLUTELY VALID.
AND DO YOUR COMPUTERS
EXPLAIN HOW MY ANCESTORS,
WHO ALSO DWELT
IN CAVERNS,
EVOLVED SUFFICIENTLY
TO ERECT STRATOS...
WHILE TROGLYTES
DID NOT?
UNEQUAL EVOLUTION
DID NOT BEGIN
UNTIL AFTER YOUR ANCESTORS
REMOVED THEMSELVES
FROM CONSTANT EXPOSURE
TO THE GAS, MR. ADVISER.
OH! PREPOSTEROUS.
THERE'S NO TIME
TO ARGUE ABOUT
THE FINDINGS NOW.
I SIMPLY PROPOSE
TO TELL VANNA
ALL ABOUT THEM.
I DOUBT WHETHER EVEN VANNA
WILL BELIEVE SUCH NONSENSE.
THIS NONSENSE MIGHT
MEAN A GREAT DEAL
TO THE TROGLYTES.
I WOULD LIKE
TO OFFER THEM
A SUPPLY OF
THESE FILTER MASKS
IN EXCHANGE
FOR THE ZIENITE
CONSIGNMENT.
I'M SORRY, CAPTAIN.
SUCH AN OFFER COULD ONLY
CAUSE MORE UNREST AMONG THEM.
I CANNOT ALLOW IT
UNTIL OUR SCIENTISTS HAVE
CHECKED THE FINDINGS.
BUT THAT
COULD TAKE DAYS!
ARE YOU AFRAID
THE FILTER MASKS
WILL WORK?
IS THAT WHY YOU DON'T
WANT THE TROGLYTES
TO TRY THEM?
YOU ARE HERE TO COMPLETE
AN EMERGENCY MISSION,
NOT CONDUCT TESTS, CAPTAIN.
I'M HERE TO GET
THAT ZIENITE.
IF THESE WILL
HELP ME GET THEM,
THEN I'LL USE THEM.
AND I FORBID IT!
YOUR FEDERATION ORDERS
DO NOT ENTITLE YOU
TO DEFY LOCAL GOVERNMENTS.
THIS COMMUNICATION
HAS ENDED.
MY DIPLOMACY
IS SOMEWHAT INADEQUATE.
WELL, IT'S PRETTY HARD
TO OVERCOME PREJUDICE.
DOESN'T GIVE US MUCH
CHOICE, DOES IT?
NOR MUCH TIME.
WE HAVE 10 HOURS
AND 40 MINUTES
TO DELIVER
THAT CONSIGNMENT
TO MERAK II.
BEAM ME DOWN TO
VANNA'S CONFINEMENT
QUARTERS.
YOU MEAN YOU'RE
GOING BACK TO STRATOS
AGAINST GOVERNMENT ORDERS?
IF VANNA DOESN'T HAVE
SOMETHING DEFINITE
TO GAIN FOR HER PEOPLE,
SHE'LL DIE RATHER THAN
TURN OVER THAT ZIENITE
CONSIGNMENT.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
THAT MIGHT CONVINCE HER.
CAPTAIN, IF YOU
ARE APPREHENDED
DELIBERATELY VIOLATING
THE HIGH ADVISERS'
ORDERS,
HE WILL BE
WITHIN HIS RIGHTS
TO HAVE YOU EXECUTED
IF HE CHOOSES.
IF YOU'RE ABOUT
TO SUGGEST THAT
YOU CONTACT VANNA,
THE ANSWER IS
NEGATIVE, SPOCK.
THAT GOES FOR YOU,
TOO, BONES.
ALLOW ME TO POINT OUT
THAT A FIRST OFFICER
IS MORE EXPENDABLE
THAN EITHER A DOCTOR
OR A CAPTAIN.
OFFICIALLY, YES,
BUT THIS MISSION IS
STRICTLY UNOFFICIAL.
NOBODY IS TO HAVE
ANY PART IN IT,
ANY RESPONSIBILITY
FOR IT, BUT MYSELF.
THAT'S AN ORDER,
SPOCK.
YOU HAVE THE CON.
STAND BY
TILL I CONTACT YOU.
VANNA...
I'VE BROUGHT YOU
A GIFT.
THERE'S A DANGEROUS
GAS IN THE MINES
THAT AFFECTS
THE DEVELOPMENT
OF THE TROGLYTES
EXPOSED TO IT
FOR A PERIOD
OF TIME.
THIS MASK WILL PREVENT
ANY FURTHER DAMAGE.
GAS FROM ZIENITE?
YES.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT
SOMETHING WHICH IS NEITHER
SEEN NOR FELT
CAN DO SO MUCH HARM.
THAT'S TRUE.
BUT AN IDEA CAN'T
BE SEEN OR FELT,
AND THAT'S WHAT'S
KEPT THE TROGLYTES
IN THE MINES
ALL THESE CENTURIES--
A MISTAKEN IDEA.
WOULD...
ALL THE TROGLYTES
WEAR THESE MASKS?
YES. I'LL SEE TO IT
THAT THE FEDERATION
ENGINEERS
CONSTRUCT THEM.
SUPPOSE PLASUS
DOES NOT AGREE?
PLASUS IS NOT
THE WHOLE GOVERNMENT.
THAT IS TRUE.
BUT THE CITY COUNCIL...
WILL NOT LISTEN
TO TROGLYTES.
AS SOON AS THE
ZIENITE IS DELIVERED
TO MERAK II,
I'LL COME BACK.
I'LL REQUEST
PERMISSION
TO MEDIATE
FOR THE TROGLYTES.
VANNA...
YOU MUST TRUST ME.
I GIVE YOU MY WORD.
CENTURIES AGO, STRATOS
WAS BUILT BY LEADERS
THAT GAVE THEIR WORD
THAT ALL INHABITANTS
WOULD LIVE THERE.
THE TROGLYTES
ARE STILL WAITING.
THE ZIENITE
CAN BE DELIVERED
IN A FEW HOURS.
YOU WON'T HAVE LONG
TO WAIT NOW.
HOURS CAN BE CENTURIES,
JUST AS WORDS
CAN BE LIES.
VANNA...
YOU MUST TRUST ME.
IF YOU DON'T,
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
WILL DIE--
A WHOLE PLANET.
THIS ZIENITE IS ALL
THAT CAN SAVE THEM.
THIS FILTER MASK
IS ALL THAT CAN SAVE
THE TROGLYTES.
TRUST ME.
PLEASE.
VERY WELL, CAPTAIN.
I WILL TRUST YOU.
THE CONSIGNMENT LIES
DEEP IN THE MINES
IN A PLACE KNOWN
ONLY TO TROGLYTES.
I CANNOT DIRECT YOU.
I MUST TAKE YOU THERE.
YOU ASKED FOR
MY TRUST, CAPTAIN.
ARE YOU UNWILLING
TO GIVE YOURS?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
IT'S THE SENTINEL
WITH MY REFRESHMENT.
WAIT. WE'LL NEED
A TRANSPORT PASS
TO LEAVE THE CITY.
MIDRO.
VANNA.
ANKA.
YOU HAVE RETURNED.
AND I'VE BROUGHT WITH ME
A HOSTAGE. SEIZE HIM!
WE HAD A BARGAIN.
WHY DID YOU BREAK IT?
DID YOU REALLY THINK
I WOULD TRUST YOU,
CAPTAIN?
I'M NOT SUCH A FOOL.
I TRUSTED YOU.
YOU THOUGHT
YOU WOULD TRICK ME
WITH YOUR TALK OF YOUR FILTER
AND YOUR UNSEEN GAS.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU
ANY MORE THAN PLASUS DOES.
THEN YOU ARE A FOOL.
THESE MASKS
WILL FREE YOU,
JUST AS I SAID.
OUR WEAPONS
ARE OUR FREEDOM,
AND YOU'VE JUST FURNISHED ME
WITH TWO VERY VALUABLE ONES--
YOURSELF AND THIS.
HOLDING ME
WON'T HELP YOU.
MY MEN WILL STILL COME
FOR THAT ZIENITE
CONSIGNMENT.
WITHOUT YOUR
COMMUNICATOR,
YOU WILL BE HARD
TO LOCATE.
THEY'LL STILL COME.
PERHAPS.
IN THE MEANTIME, TASTE
OF OUR EXISTENCE, CAPTAIN.
DIG AS THE TROGLYTES DO.
AS THE TROGLYTES DO--
WITHOUT THAT MASK
I HAVEN'T--
WITH YOUR BARE
HANDS, CAPTAIN.
Spock: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
SUPPLEMENTAL. STARDATE 5819.3.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK
REPORTING.
CAPTAIN KIRK BEAMED
DOWN TO STRATOS
TO ATTEMPT TO WIN THE CONFIDENCE
OF THE REBEL TROGLYTES.
UNLESS HE HAS MADE HIS ESCAPE
FROM STRATOS TO THE MINES,
HIS LIFE IS IN DANGER
FROM THE HIGH ADVISER.
THE CAPTAIN HAS NOT INFORMED US
OF HIS PROGRESS.
FOR OUR PART,
WE MUST MAINTAIN SILENCE.
WE CAN BE OF NO HELP TO HIM
WITHOUT JEOPARDIZING HIS LIFE.
YOU DIG WELL,
CAPTAIN.
THE UNSEEN GAS
DOESN'T SEEM TO
BE HARMING YOU.
IT TAKES A WHILE
FOR ITS EFFECTS
TO BE NOTICED.
NEVERTHELESS,
YOU WON'T BE
NEEDING THIS.
ANKA, DEPOSIT THIS
ON THE TRANSPORT
PLATFORM
SO PLASUS WILL KNOW
WE HAVE SOMETHING
MORE VALUABLE
TO BARGAIN WITH
THAN OUR MORTAYS
AND THONGS.
Anka: YOU ARE CLEVER,
VANNA--VERY CLEVER.
THE SEARCHERS
WILL BE COMING
SOON, MIDRO.
GO TO
THE OTHER MINES
AND TELL THE TROGLYTES
TO POST WATCHES.
WHAT OF HIM?
I WILL SEE THAT
HE DOESN'T ESCAPE.
IF WE KILL HIM,
THERE WILL BE NO NEED TO SEE.
A DEAD HOSTAGE
IS OF NO VALUE, MIDRO.
ONLY THE TROGLYTES
WILL KNOW.
I BROUGHT HIM HERE,
AND I WILL SAY
WHAT IS TO BE DONE.
YOU ARE NOT
THE ONLY DISRUPTER.
I, TOO, CAN SAY.
AND YOU DO NOTHING
BUT ARGUE?
THE SEARCHERS
WILL BE HERE SOON.
WHEN ANKA RETURNS,
WE WILL ALL SAY.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU DISRUPTERS
ARE BARGAINING FOR--
THE RIGHT TO KILL
EVERYONE?
MIDRO IS A CHILD.
THE MASKS
CAN CHANGE THAT.
RETURN TO
THE DIGGING, CAPTAIN.
HOW LONG DO YOU PLAN ON
KEEPING ME HERE?
PROVIDING MIDRO DOESN'T
KILL ME, OF COURSE.
UNTIL WE HAVE HELP
IN THE MINES
AND OUR HOMES
ARE IN THE CLOUDS.
THAT'S QUITE A WHILE--
LONGER THAN I EXPECTED.
[RUMBLING]
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
WE'RE SEALED IN!
COMPLETELY.
BUT SOON THE ATMOSPHERE
WILL GO. WE'LL DIE!
DIE? FROM SOMETHING
THAT CAN'T BE SEEN?
YOU ASTOUND ME, VANNA.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, COME IN.
SPOCK HERE.
WE'VE BEEN TRYING
TO MAKE CONTACT, CAPTAIN.
IS ANYTHING WRONG?
NOTHING, MR. SPOCK.
ARE YOU LOCKED IN
ON ME?
LOCKED IN AND READY
TO BEAM UP CONSIGNMENT.
CIRCUMSTANCES DICTATE
A SLIGHT VARIATION,
SPOCK.
STANDING BY
FOR INSTRUCTIONS.
HOLD ON
THESE COORDINATES.
LOCATE THE HIGH ADVISER
AND BEAM HIM
TO THESE COORDINATES
IMMEDIATELY,
WITHOUT ADVANCE
COMMUNICATION.
REPEAT--WITHOUT
ADVANCE COMMUNICATION.
HAVE YOU GOT THAT,
SPOCK?
INSTRUCTIONS CLEAR.
I SHALL CARRY THEM OUT
IMMEDIATELY.
SPOCK OUT.
YOU WOULD SEAL PLASUS
HERE, ALSO?
FOR WHAT PURPOSE?
I'M PREPARING
A DEMONSTRATION...
ON THE EFFECTS
OF UNBELIEVED GAS.
BEAM THE HIGH ADVISER
DOWN WITHOUT WARNING,
DID HE SAY?
THAT'S NOT AN EXACT QUOTE,
MR. SCOTT.
HOWEVER, IT DOES
EXPRESS THE THOUGHT.
I'D LIKE TO SEE
THE ADVISER'S FACE.
YOU WILL HAVE
THAT OPPORTUNITY.
THE CAPTAIN DID SAY
IMMEDIATELY, DID HE NOT?
NOW, THAT
IS AN EXACT QUOTE,
MR. SCOTT,
AND I SUGGEST YOU HANDLE
THE TRANSPORTER YOURSELF.
THIS COULD BE
VERY DELICATE
AS A PROBLEM
IN TRANSPORTING FOR US
AND IN DIPLOMACY
FOR THE CAPTAIN.
AYE.
SOMETHING'S UPSETTING
YOU, DROXINE.
NO, FATHER.
WHAT IS IT?
TELL ME.
NO, REALLY,
I'M NOT UPSET.
I WAS JUST STANDING HERE
LOOKING INTO SPACE
AND WONDERING WHETHER OR NOT
HE WOULD RETURN.
HE WILL NEVER RETURN.
I'VE SEEN TO THAT.
BUT THE ZIENITE
IS SO IMPORTANT TO HIM.
HE MUST HAVE IT.
IT WILL BE DELIVERED
IF WE HAVE TO KILL
EVERY TROGLYTE BELOW,
IT WILL BE DELIVERED.
BY THAT TIME,
IT MAY BE TOO LATE.
PERHAPS HE DOES
HAVE A METHOD--
HE KNOWS NOTHING
EXCEPT HOW TO
DESTROY OUR POWER
AND OUR SOCIETY.
I FORBID YOU EVER TO
SPEAK OF CAPTAIN KIRK,
EVEN TO THINK OF HIM.
Scotty:
TRANSPORTER ROOM
TO MR. SPOCK.
SPOCK HERE.
I'VE LOCKED INTO
THE COORDINATES
OF THE CLOUD CITY
COUNCIL GALLERY.
READY TO TRANSPORT
THE HIGH ADVISER.
WE HAVE TO DELAY.
WHAT'S WRONG.
I'M PICKING UP
TWO LIFE FORMS
IN THE GALLERY.
THEY ARE
INSEPARABLY CLOSE
TO ONE ANOTHER.
WE CANNOT TRANSPORT
ONE WITHOUT THE OTHER.
DID YOU SAY THE WORD
"IMMEDIATELY"
WAS AN EXACT QUOTE
OF THE CAPTAIN'S ORDER?
PRECISELY, MR. SCOTT.
WELL?
ARE WE GOING TO DO IT
AS IN THE ORDER?
UNTIL THE HIGH ADVISER
IS ALONE
OR CAN BE ISOLATED,
THE CAPTAIN
WILL HAVE TO WAIT,
UNLESS YOU HAVE
AN ALTERNATIVE.
I'LL GIVE IT
FURTHER THOUGHT.
I WASN'T THINKING
OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
IT'S THE ONE WITH THOSE
EXQUISITELY-SHAPED EARS.
HIS NAME IS SPOCK.
HE'S THE ONE
I WAS THINKING ABOUT.
DID YOU KNOW THAT
HE HAS THE MOST
INCREDIBLY SENSITIVE HEARING?
WHY, I ALMOST BELIEVE
IF I STOOD HERE
AND CALLED OUT TO HIM,
HE WOULD HEAR MY INVITATION
TO COME AND VISIT WITH US
FOR A LITTLE WHILE LONGER.
OH, HE'S NO BETTER
THAN HIS FRIEND.
SHALL WE TRY?
WHAT IS IT?
THE DISRUPTER VANNA
HAS DISAPPEARED.
HER GUARD WAS FOUND
HALF-UNCONSCIOUS.
HE'D BEEN ATTACKED
BY CAPTAIN KIRK.
WHERE IS
CAPTAIN KIRK?
HE DID NOT KNOW, SIR.
HE DID NOT
REGAIN HIS SENSES
UNTIL I CAME TO HIS AID.
THIS IS THE KIND
OF REASON THEY USE
TO PERSUADE US.
THEY ARE DESPERATE.
I WILL HEAR NO MORE
DEFENSE OF THEM.
I'M SURE MR. SPOCK
WOULD NOT BEHAVE SO.
LEAVE HERE AT ONCE.
GO TO YOUR MUSIC.
FATHER, ARE WE SO SURE
OF OUR METHODS
THAT WE NEVER QUESTION
WHAT WE DO?
SPOCK TO
TRANSPORTER ROOM.
SCOTT HERE.
LOCK IN ON COUNCIL
GALLERY COORDINATES.
LOCKED IN, SIR.
ENERGIZE.
AYE, SIR.
ENERGIZING.
HOW ARE YOU DOING,
MR. SCOTT?
FINE, MR. SPOCK.
THE HIGH ADVISER
IS MATERIALIZING
ON THE PLATFORM.
BEAM HIM DOWN
TO CAPTAIN KIRK
IMMEDIATELY.
ENERGIZING, SIR.
HE'S ON HIS WAY
TO THE CAPTAIN.
GOOD WORK, MR. SCOTT.
THE ADVISER LOOKED
MIGHTY ANGRY.
I HOPE HE DOESN'T
GIVE THE CAPTAIN
TOO MUCH TROUBLE.
THE CAPTAIN WILL EMPLOY
HIS USUAL DIPLOMATIC BALM.
ABDUCTION
OF A PLANET OFFICIAL
IS A SERIOUS CRIME.
YOU WILL PAY FOR THIS,
I PROMISE YOU.
NOT UNTIL YOU'RE CONVINCED
OF THE EFFECTS
OF THE ZIENITE GAS,
MR. ADVISER.
WHAT EFFECTS?
I'VE BEEN HERE
NEARLY AN HOUR
OF YOUR EARTH TIME--
YOU AND VANNA
EVEN LONGER.
I SEE NO CHANGES
IN ANY OF US.
PERHAPS YOU NEED
CLOSER EXPOSURE.
FILL THAT CONTAINER.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT I DIG ZIENITE?
I INSIST.
YOU WILL INDEED
PAY FOR THIS.
YOU, TOO, VANNA.
YOU, TOO. DIG!
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
KIRK HERE. WHAT IS IT?
CONTACT CHECK, CAPTAIN.
IT HAS BEEN
OVER AN HOUR
SINCE YOUR LAST
COMMUNICATION.
YOUR ORDERS
ARE TO STAND BY.
NOW CARRY THEM OUT!
KIRK OUT.
STANDING BY,
CAPTAIN.
HOWEVER, LET ME
REMIND YOU WE HAVE
ONLY 5 HOURS LEFT--
THAT WAS VERY
UNLIKE THE CAPTAIN.
CAN THE ZIENITE
BE AFFECTING HIM?
Vanna: I GROW FAINT.
THE OXYGEN IS GOING.
SHE'S RIGHT.
KIRK, TRANSPORT US
OUT OF HERE.
WE'LL LEAVE
WHEN THE GAS HAS EFFECT.
IT WILL NEVER
TAKE EFFECT!
TRANSPORT US
OUT OF HERE!
DIG!
IMBECILE.
WE'LL DIE!
I SAID DIG!
I AM HIGH ADVISER
OF ALL THE PLANET.
I WILL TAKE
NO MORE ORDERS!
ONE MORE STEP
AND I'LL KILL YOU.
THE GAS. CAPTAIN,
YOU WERE RIGHT.
IT'S TAKING EFFECT!
CAPTAIN, YOU WERE RIGHT.
ARE YOU AS BRAVE
WITH MORTAY
AS YOU ARE
WITH A PHASER?
BOTH WILL KILL.
[COMMUNICATOR BEEPS]
Vanna: ENTERPRISE.
ENTERPRISE, HELP!
ENTERPRISE!
ENTERPRISE.
SPOCK HERE.
Vanna: THEY'LL KILL
EACH OTHER! HELP US!
HELP US!
Vanna: ENTERPRISE!
ENTERPRISE!
CAPTAIN!
THE ZIENITE GAS
HAS AFFECTED YOU.
CAPTAIN!
THE ZIENITE GAS!
THE ZIENITE GAS.
LOOK OUT, JIM!
WELL.
IT SEEMS MY LITTLE
DEMONSTRATION WAS...
QUITE A SUCCESS.
I DON'T LIKE FILTERS
OR EVEN MASKS.
I LIKE THE WORD
"PROTECTOR"
MUCH BETTER.
DON'T YOU?
IT IS LESS TECHNICAL,
THEREFORE LESS ACCURATE,
BUT PERHAPS MORE
GENERALLY DESCRIPTIVE
OF THE FUNCTION.
IT APPEARS YOU HAVE
WHAT YOU CAME FOR
AFTER ALL.
Vanna: THE CAPTAIN
WILL HAVE HIS ZIENITE,
JUST AS I AGREED.
AGREED? THERE'S
NO SUCH WORD
IN THE TROGLYTE
VOCABULARY.
THE CAPTAIN WILL HAVE
HIS ZIENITE.
NO THANKS
TO ANY AGREEMENT
BY YOU.
IT HAD TO BE
OBTAINED BY FORCE.
BECAUSE IT IS
THE ONLY WAY
WE CAN OBTAIN
WHAT IS DUE US.
HOW ABOUT
YOUR EDUCATION?
WAS THAT BY FORCE?
IT SERVED YOUR PURPOSE
AT THE TIME.
YOU COULD HAVE HAD
THOSE FILTERS,
FOR ALL THE GOOD
IT WILL DO YOU.
THEY WILL BE
VERY EFFECTIVE, SIR.
THEY'VE BEEN
SEVERELY TESTED,
AND THE TROGLYTES
WILL NO LONGER SUFFER
FROM RETARDATION
AND EMOTIONAL
DIFFICULTIES.
THEY WILL ALL BE
LIKE HER--
UNGRATEFUL,
VINDICTIVE.
YES. OUR DEMANDS
HAVE JUST BEGUN.
HERE IS THE ZIENITE,
CAPTAIN...
JUST AS I PROMISED.
THANK YOU, VANNA.
STRATOS IS SO PLEASANT
AND SO BEAUTIFUL.
I THINK I'M AFRAID
TO LEAVE IT.
THERE IS GREAT BEAUTY
IN THE KNOWLEDGE
THAT LIES BELOW...
AND ONLY ONE WAY
TO REALLY EXPERIENCE IT.
I SHALL GO
TO THE MINES.
I NO LONGER WISH
TO BE LIMITED
TO THE CLOUDS.
IS...
YOUR PLANET
LIKE THIS ONE?
NO.
NO, VULCAN
IS QUITE DIFFERENT.
SOMEDAY I SHOULD
LIKE TO VISIT IT.
PERHAPS SOME FORM
OF MEDIATION CAN BE HELPFUL
IN YOUR DIFFICULTIES.
THE FEDERATION BUREAU
OF INDUSTRIALIZATION
MAY BE OF AID TO YOU.
I WILL TOLERATE
ABSOLUTELY NO INTERFERENCE.
YOU WILL NOT SET FOOT HERE
AS LONG AS I RULE!
BELIEVE ME, SIR,
I HAVE NEITHER THE TIME
NOR THE DESIRE
TO RETURN HERE.
ONLY ANSWERING
YOUR CHARGES AGAINST ME
WILL FORCE ME BACK.
AND I SHALL PRESS THEM!
YOU ARE GUILTY
OF ABDUCTION, CAPTAIN.
AND YOU'RE GUILTY
OF ATTACKING
A STARSHIP COMMANDER
AND PLOTTING
AGAINST HIS LIFE!
CAPTAIN, PERHAPS
BOTH INCIDENTS
ARE BEST FORGOTTEN.
YES, VANNA.
THEY NEVER HAPPENED.
MR. ADVISER?
MR. SPOCK, LET'S GET
THAT ZIENITE DELIVERED.
I BELIEVE WE ONLY HAVE
3 HOURS LEFT.
2 HOURS, 59 MINUTES,
TO BE EXACT, CAPTAIN.
KIRK TO ENTERPRISE.
MR. SCOTT, BEAM US UP.