Kirk: CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 5928.5.
THE "ENTERPRISE" HAS RECEIVED
A DISTRESS CALL
FROM A GROUP OF SCIENTISTS
ON CAMUS II
WHO WERE EXPLORING THE RUINS
OF A DEAD CIVILIZATION.
THEIR SITUATION
IS DESPERATE.
TWO OF THE SURVIVORS ARE
THE EXPEDITION SURGEON
DR. COLEMAN
AND THE LEADER
OF THE EXPEDITION,
DR. JANICE LESTER.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH HER?
EXPOSURE
TO RADIATION.
WHAT FORM OF RADIATION
WAS IT?
NOTHING I'VE EVER
ENCOUNTERED.
[DR. LESTER MOANS]
JANICE...
YOU MUST REMAIN
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
THOSE ARE DOCTOR'S
ORDERS, NOT MINE.
Spock: CAPTAIN,
TRICORDER PICKING UP
VERY FAINT
LIFE READINGS
APPROXIMATELY
700 METERS FROM HERE.
HELP WILL
HAVE TO BE IMMEDIATE.
UH...UH...
PERHAPS YOUR PRESENCE
WILL QUIET HER.
I HOPED I WOULDN'T
SEE YOU AGAIN.
I DON'T BLAME YOU.
THE YEAR
WE WERE TOGETHER
AT STARFLEET
IS THE ONLY TIME
IN MY LIFE
I WAS ALIVE.
I NEVER STOPPED YOU
FROM GOING ON
WITH YOUR SPACE WORK.
YOUR WORLD OF
STARSHIP CAPTAINS
DOESN'T ADMIT WOMEN.
IT ISN'T FAIR.
NO, IT ISN'T,
AND YOU PUNISHED
AND TORTURED ME
BECAUSE OF IT.
I LOVED YOU.
WE COULD HAVE ROAMED
AMONG THE STARS.
WE'D HAVE KILLED
EACH OTHER.
IT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN BETTER.
[BEAM FIRES]
Kirk: SPACE--THE FINAL FRONTIER.
THESE ARE THE VOYAGES
OF THE STARSHIP "ENTERPRISE,"
ITS 5-YEAR MISSION--
TO EXPLORE
STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
TO SEEK OUT NEW LIFE
AND NEW CIVILIZATIONS...
TO BOLDLY GO WHERE
NO MAN HAS GONE BEFORE.
[LAUGHING]
YOU HAD YOUR CHANCE,
CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU SHOULD HAVE SMOTHERED
THE LIFE IN ME.
THEN THEY WOULD HAVE SAID,
DR. JANICE LESTER DIED
OF RADIATION POISONING
IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
WHY DIDN'T YOU DO IT?
YOU ALWAYS WANTED TO.
DIDN'T YOU?
YOU HAD THE STRENGTH
TO DO IT.
BUT YOU WERE AFRAID.
YOU WERE ALWAYS AFRAID.
NOW JANICE LESTER TAKES
THE PLACE OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
I ALREADY POSSESS
YOUR PHYSICAL STRENGTH.
ONLY THIS...CAPTAIN KIRK
IS NOT AFRAID TO KILL.
[MOANS]
NOW YOU'LL KNOW
THE INDIGNITY
OF BEING A WOMAN.
[MOANING]
FOR YOU, THIS AGONY
WILL SOON PASS,
AS IT HAS FOR ME.
QUIET. QUIET!
BELIEVE ME,
IT'S BETTER TO BE DEAD...
THAN TO LIVE ALONE
IN THE BODY OF A WOMAN.
[THUD]
IT'S BETTER TO BE DEAD.
[FOOTSTEPS]
DR. McCOY...
YOUR REPORT.
WE WERE
TOO LATE, JIM.
THERE'S NOTHING
COULD BE DONE.
WAS IT RADIATION,
AS SUGGESTED?
NO, I BELIEVE
IT WAS CELEBIUM.
HOWEVER, DR. COLEMAN
DISAGREES.
TO BE SPECIFIC
IS ESSENTIAL
BECAUSE THE TREATMENT
OF CELEBIUM IS QUITE--
DR. McCOY.
DID YOU NOTICE
ANY UNUSUAL SYMPTOMS
WHILE WE WERE GONE?
NO, NOTHING AT ALL.
SHE WAS UNCONSCIOUS
ALL THE TIME.
DR. LESTER
IS NEAR DEATH.
PERHAPS THE SHOCK
OF KNOWING WHAT
HAPPENED TO HER STAFF
IS PART OF THE PROBLEM.
I'M SURE IT IS.
BEAMING HER UP TO
THE "ENTERPRISE" WOULD BE
LESS HARMFUL THAN WAITING.
I--I DON'T KNOW.
I'M NOT SURE.
CAPTAIN KIRK
TO THE "ENTERPRISE."
Scotty:
MR. SCOTT, SIR.
SCOTT...
PREPARE TO BEAM
THE LANDING PARTY ABOARD,
PLUS TWO OTHERS,
ONE CRITICALLY ILL.
HAVE A MEDICAL TEAM
STANDING BY TO RECEIVE
THE PATIENT.
CAPTAIN KIRK OUT.
PREPARE TO BEAM ABOARD.
DR. COLEMAN,
ACCOMPANY THE PATIENT
TO THE SICK BAY.
MR. SPOCK, TAKE
THE SHIP OUT OF ORBIT.
RESUME
DESIGNATED COURSE.
DR. McCOY.
DR. McCOY,
YOU AND DR. COLEMAN
SEEM TO DISAGREE
ON DIAGNOSIS.
NO, NOT ENTIRELY.
WE BOTH AGREE
IT'S RADIATION.
DR. COLEMAN
ISN'T PREPARED TO SAY
WHAT FORM OF RADIATION.
WILL IT AFFECT
YOUR ARRIVING AT
A CORRECT TREATMENT?
IT'S CRUCIAL.
WELL...
THIS IS ESPECIALLY
DISTURBING TO ME
FOR...
PERSONAL REASONS.
OH? I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU KNEW HER THAT WELL.
OH, YES. IT'S
BEEN A LONG TIME
SINCE I SAW HER.
I WALKED OUT ON HER
WHEN IT BECAME SERIOUS.
WELL, YOU MUST HAVE BEEN
VERY YOUNG AT THE TIME, JIM.
YOUTH DOESN'T
EXCUSE EVERYTHING,
DR. McCOY.
IT'S A VERY UNHAPPY
MEMORY FOR ME.
OH, I DIDN'T
REALIZE THAT.
I SHALL DO EVERYTHING
IN MY POWER.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
DR. LESTER IS CERTAINLY
A VERY LUCKY YOUNG PERSON
TO HAVE ESCAPED.
YES, VERY LUCKY.
VERY LUCKY.
[MOANING]
IT JUST BEGAN.
WELL, YOU BETTER PUT
A STOP TO IT!
IF YOU ALLOW DR. LESTER
TO BECOME FULLY CONSCIOUS,
SHE'LL KNOW
WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
PROBABLY NO ONE
WILL BELIEVE IT.
PROBABLY?
THAT'S ALL
WE CAN ASK FOR.
HOW CAN DEATH
BE EXPLAINED NOW?
[MOANING]
I TELL YOU,
IT CAN'T CONTINUE.
YOU KILLED EVERY ONE
OF THE STAFF.
YOU SENT THEM
WHERE YOU KNEW
THE CELEBIUM
SHIELDING WAS WEAK.
NOW, WHY DIDN'T YOU
KILL HIM?
YOU HAD THE PERFECT
OPPORTUNITY.
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH TIME.
I GAVE YOU
EVERY MINUTE
YOU ASKED FOR.
HE HUNG ON
TO LIFE TOO HARD.
I COULDN'T--
YOU COULDN'T BECAUSE
YOU LOVE HIM.
YOU WANT ME TO BE
HIS MURDERER.
LOVE...HIM?
I LOVE THE LIFE HE LED,
THE POWER OF
A STARSHIP COMMANDER.
IT'S MY LIFE NOW.
I WON'T BECOME
A MURDERER.
YOU ARE A MURDERER!
YOU KNEW
IT WAS CELEBIUM.
YOU COULD HAVE
TREATED THEM FOR IT.
YOU'RE A MURDERER
MANY TIMES OVER.
[MOANING]
JIM, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I THOUGHT MY PRESENCE
MIGHT QUIET DR. LESTER.
IT SEEMS TO HAVE HAD
THE OPPOSITE EFFECT.
IT HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH YOU.
IT'S A SYMPTOM
OF THE DEVELOPING
RADIATION ILLNESS.
TESTS WITH
THE SHIP'S EQUIPMENT
SHOWS NO SIGNS OF
INTERNAL RADIATION
DAMAGE, DR. COLEMAN.
DIDN'T DR. LESTER'S STAFF
BECOME DELIRIOUS BEFORE
THEY WENT OFF AND DIED?
UH, YES, CAPTAIN, YES.
DR. LESTER COULD BE
SUFFERING FROM
A PHASER STUN
AS FAR AS
THE SYMPTOMS
I CAN DETECT, JIM.
DR. COLEMAN,
DR. McCOY HAS HAD
A GREAT DEAL OF EXPERIENCE
WITH RADIATION EXPOSURE
ON-BOARD THE "ENTERPRISE."
I AM GUIDED
BY HIS OPINION.
DR. LESTER
AND HER STAFF
HAVE BEEN UNDER
MY SUPERVISION
FOR TWO YEARS NOW.
IF YOU DON'T FOLLOW
MY RECOMMENDATIONS,
RESPONSIBILITY
FOR HER HEALTH
OR HER DEATH...
WILL BE YOURS.
UH...
DR. McCOY, I AM SORRY,
BUT I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO TAKE YOU OFF THE CASE
AND TURN IT OVER
TO DR. COLEMAN.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS.
ON THIS SHIP, MY MEDICAL
AUTHORITY IS FINAL.
IF DR. COLEMAN WANTS TO ASSUME
THE FULL RESPONSIBILITY,
LET HIM DO IT.
I WON'T ALLOW IT.
IT'S DONE.
DR. COLEMAN, YOUR PATIENT.
UH... UH...
DR. COLEMAN, DIDN'T YOU
SUGGEST A SEDATION
TO REST THE PATIENT?
YES, CAPTAIN.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY,
JIM.
CAN'T YOU SEE SHE'S
COMING AROUND?
[MOANING]
DR. COLEMAN?
NURSE, ADMINISTER
THE SEDATIVE.
A SEDATIVE IS NOT
WISE AT THIS TIME,
CAPTAIN.
NURSE CHAPEL,
YOU HAVE YOUR ORDERS.
FOLLOW
YOUR INSTRUCTIONS.
OH...
AM I...
REALLY LOSING
COMMAND OF
THE "ENTERPRISE"?
NO.
OH, NO. BAD DREAM.
OH,
BAD DREAM.
Kirk's voice: JAMES KIRK IS
RETURNING TO CONSCIOUSNESS
IN THE BODY OF JANICE LESTER.
THE "ENTERPRISE" IS PROCEEDING
TO ITS NEXT MISSION
ON THE COURSE SET FOR IT
BEFORE I TOOK OVER COMMAND.
NOW THE YEARS I SPENT
STUDYING EVERY SINGLE DETAIL
OF THE SHIP'S OPERATION
WILL BE TESTED.
WITH A LITTLE EXPERIENCE,
I WILL BE INVULNERABLE
TO SUSPICION.
Kirk's voice: AT LAST I ATTAINED
WHAT IS MY JUST DUE--
COMMAND OF A STARSHIP,
ALL THE MONTHS OF PREPARATION
NOW COME TO FRUITION.
COURSE, MR. CHEKOV?
127 MARK 8.
MR. SULU, SET SPEED
AT WARP FACTOR 2.
WARP FACTOR 2,
SIR.
[INDISTINCT RADIO COMMUNICATIONS
IN BACKGROUND]
MR. CHEKOV,
PLOT A COURSE FOR
THE BENECIA COLONY.
DIRECT COURSE
TO BENECIA--
373 MARK 8.
HOW LONG TO THE COLONY
AT OUR PRESENT SPEED?
48 HOURS, SIR.
MR. SULU, SET COURSE
FOR THE COLONY--
373 MARK 8.
AYE, SIR.
CAPTAIN, THAT WILL DELAY
OUR WORK AT BETA AURIGAE.
IT MEANS
REVERSING COURSE.
YES, IT CAN'T BE HELPED.
WE MUST TAKE DR. LESTER
TO A PLACE WHERE SHE
CAN BE TREATED.
MAY I POINT OUT
THAT STARBASE TWO
IS ON THE DIRECT ROUTE
TO OUR DESTINATION?
HOW LONG TO STARBASE TWO?
72 HOURS, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S 24 HOURS TOO LONG.
DR. LESTER'S CONDITION
IS INCREASINGLY SERIOUS.
CONTINUE PRESENT COURSE.
AYE, SIR.
SIR, IF THE DIAGNOSIS
OF DR. LESTER'S ILLNESS
IS THE CRITICAL PROBLEM,
THEN THE BENECIA COLONY
IS DEFINITELY NOT
THE PLACE FOR HER.
THEIR MEDICAL FACILITIES
ARE THE MOST PRIMITIVE.
THEY WILL HAVE TO SERVE.
STARBASE TWO
IS FULLY EQUIPPED
AND STAFFED
WITH THE NECESSARY
SPECIALISTS
TO DETERMINE EXACTLY
WHAT IS WRONG
WITH THE DOCTOR.
IS THAT NOT CRUCIAL
TO YOUR DECISION?
THANK YOU, MR. SPOCK,
BUT THE FACILITIES
WILL BE OF LITTLE USE
IF DR. LESTER'S DEAD.
TIME IS OF THE ESSENCE.
CONTINUE PRESENT COURSE.
AT MAXIMUM SPEED...
STARBASE TWO WOULD STILL
MEET THE EMERGENCY.
CAPTAIN, SHALL I ADVISE
STARFLEET COMMAND
OF THE CHANGE OF PLAN?
NO CHANGE OF PLAN HAS
BEEN ORDERED, LIEUTENANT.
OUR ARRIVAL AT BETA AURIGAE
WILL MERELY BE DELAYED.
OUR GRAVITATIONAL STUDIES
OF THAT BINARY SYSTEM
WILL NOT SUFFER,
AND A LIFE MAY BE SAVED.
THAT IS NOT UNUSUAL PROCEDURE
FOR THE "ENTERPRISE."
Spock: SIR, I BELIEVE
THAT STARFLEET WILL
HAVE TO BE NOTIFIED
THAT OUR RENDEZVOUS WITH
THE STARSHIP "POTEMKIN"
WILL NOT TAKE PLACE
AS SCHEDULED.
MR. SPOCK,
IF YOU'D CONCENTRATE
ON THE AREAS
FOR WHICH YOU
ARE RESPONSIBLE,
STARFLEET COMMAND
WOULD HAVE BEEN
INFORMED ALREADY.
SINCE THE CAPTAIN
USUALLY DEALS DIRECTLY
WITH STARFLEET
IN THESE MATTERS,
I ASSUMED THAT
MY SUGGESTIONS MIGHT
BE DEEMED INTERFERENCE.
INFORM STARFLEET
OF THE DELAY, LIEUTENANT.
AYE, SIR.
CONTINUE PRESENT COURSE.
INCREASE SPEED
TO WARP FACTOR 6.
I'LL LET MY RECORD
SPEAK FOR ME.
WHY ARE YOU BEING
SO DEFENSIVE?
THERE'S NO IMPLIED
CRITICISM OF YOU
IN MY ORDER TO REMOVE YOU
FROM THE CASE.
THAT IS NOT
THE REASON I'M HERE.
I'M HERE BECAUSE
DR. COLEMAN'S RECORD
STATES THAT
HE'S INCOMPETENT.
THAT'S THE OPINION
OF AN INDIVIDUAL.
NO, SIR.
THAT IS THE OPINION
OF STARFLEET
COMMAND.
I CHECKED WITH THEM.
AND DR. COLEMAN
WAS REMOVED
FROM HIS POST
AS CHIEF MEDICAL
OFFICER OF HIS SHIP
FOR ADMINISTRATIVE
INCOMPETENCE.
THERE ARE
NO ADMINISTRATIVE
DUTIES REQUIRED HERE.
AS WELL AS FLAGRANT
MEDICAL BLUNDERS.
PROMOTIONS AND DEMOTIONS
CAN BE POLITICALLY
MANEUVERED.
YOU KNOW THAT, BONES.
NOT IN STARFLEET
HEADQUARTERS,
CAPTAIN,
AND CERTAINLY NOT
IN THE SURGEON
GENERAL'S OFFICE.
I'M AFRAID THE ORDER
WILL HAVE TO STAND.
I CAN ONLY SAY...
THAT DR. COLEMAN'S
EXPERIENCE WITH WHAT
HAPPENED ON THE PLANET
HAD TO BE THE DECIDING
FACTOR HERE.
I'M SURE THAT YOU CAN
APPRECIATE THAT.
I APPRECIATE
THE FACT THAT YOU HAD
A DECISION TO MAKE.
I ALSO FIND MYSELF
IN THAT POSITION NOW, JIM,
AND I'M ASKING YOU TO REPORT
FOR AN EXAMINATION.
WHY?
WHAT DO YOU
BASE THAT ON?
DEVELOPMENT OF EMOTIONAL
INSTABILITY
AND ERRATIC
MENTAL ATTITUDES
SINCE RETURNING
FROM THAT PLANET.
YOU'LL NEVER MAKE
THAT CHARGE STICK.
ANY FOOL CAN SEE
WHY YOU'RE DOING THIS.
I'LL LET STARFLEET COMMAND
BE THE JUDGE OF MY MOTIVES.
I WON'T SUBMIT TO
THIS PETTY SEARCH
FOR REVENGE.
BUT YOU WILL SUBMIT
TO STARFLEET REGULATIONS,
AND THEY STATE
THAT THE SHIP'S SURGEON
WILL REQUIRE FULL EXAMINATION
OF ANY CREW MEMBER
THAT HE HAS DOUBTS ABOUT,
INCLUDING THE CAPTAIN.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
CAPTAIN KIRK HERE.
SULU HERE, CAPTAIN.
STARFLEET COMMAND IS
REQUESTING ADDITIONAL
DETAILS ON THE DELAY.
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
PULSE, PRESSURE...
BLOOD COUNT--
ALL BODY FUNCTIONS NORMAL.
THEN WHY AM I HERE?
DR. McCOY?
DR. McCOY--
QUIET WOULD BE
BEST FOR YOU.
WHERE IS DR. McCOY?
I'M IN CHARGE NOW.
BRING DR. McCOY AT ONCE.
HE IS IN COMMAND OF
MEDICINE ON THIS SHIP.
HE WAS TAKEN OFF YOUR CASE
BY CAPTAIN KIRK.
BY CAPTAIN KIRK?
IT WAS DONE FOR
YOUR OWN PROTECTION,
DR. LESTER.
I AM NOT JANICE LESTER.
SHE DID THIS TO ME.
NOW, HOW CAN I
MAKE YOU UNDERSTAND?
JANICE HAS DRIVEN
HERSELF MAD
WITH JEALOUSY, HATRED,
AND AMBITION.
NURSE CHAPEL,
BRING MR. SPOCK
AND DR. McCOY
TO ME AT ONCE.
NOW,
THEY MUST BELIEVE
I AM NOT
JANICE LESTER.
I AM IMPRISONED
IN HER BODY,
BUT I AM NOT
JANICE LESTER.
SHE IS SUFFERING
FROM THE DELUSION
OF BEING CAPTAIN KIRK.
I AM NOT
JANICE LESTER.
THE PARANOIA
HAS BEEN DEVELOPING
FOR THE PAST 6 MONTHS.
THE RADIATION SEEMS
TO HAVE INTENSIFIED IT.
SHE MUST BE KEPT
SEDATED.
SHALL I PREPARE
A MILD SEDATIVE, DOCTOR?
OF COURSE.
YOU ARE INSANE,
DR. LESTER.
Lester's voice:
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE UNKNOWN.
I HAVE LOST TRACK OF TIME.
I AM STILL HELD CAPTIVE
IN A STRANGE BODY
AND SEPARATED
FROM ALL MY CREW.
I MUST HAVE SOUNDED
QUITE MAD TO YOU BEFORE.
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
WOULD HAVE COMPLETELY
BROKEN MOST OF US.
WELL, I'LL
BE ALL RIGHT NOW.
COULD I SEE
YOUR DR. McCOY?
I'M AFRAID THAT'S AGAINST
DR. COLEMAN'S ORDERS.
OH.
IS A VISIT BY THAT
VERY KIND MR. SPOCK
TO BE ALLOWED?
PERHAPS THAT CAN BE ARRANGED
BEFORE WE REACH
THE BENECIA COLONY.
THE BENECIA COLONY?
BUT ISN'T THE "ENTERPRISE"
GOING TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH THE "POTEMKIN"
AT BETA AURIGAE?
WELL, FIRST WE HAVE TO LET YOU
RECUPERATE AT BENECIA.
YOU'LL FEEL BETTER
IF YOU HAVE A LITTLE.
WELL, I'LL TRY.
THANK YOU.
OH, IT IS GOOD.
COULD I FINISH IT
SLOWLY, NURSE CHAPEL?
WELL--
I PROMISE I'LL BE GOOD.
WELL, I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I'M GLAD YOU'RE FEELING
SO MUCH BETTER.
THESE TESTS SHOULD HELP ME
PINPOINT THE CAUSE
OF JIM'S ILLNESS.
GOOD. KNOWLEDGE
OF THE CAPTAIN'S
ABERRANT BEHAVIOR
IS SPREADING
THROUGH THE SHIP.
THE CREW IS BECOMING
INCREASINGLY TENSE.
YES, WELL,
WHAT WORRIES ME MOST
IS THAT JIM SEEMS
COMPLETELY UNAWARE
THAT SOMETHING IS
WRONG WITH HIM.
NOW, WE'VE GOT
TO MAKE HIM REALIZE
THAT SOMETHING SERIOUS
IS HAPPENING
BEFORE TREATMENT
CAN EVEN BEGIN.
I'M AFRAID THAT IS
A FORLORN HOPE, DOCTOR.
THE ILLNESS APPEARS
TO BE PRIMARILY MENTAL.
WELL, ONE OF US SHOULD
BE ABLE TO GET TO HIM.
I...I DON'T KNOW.
I KEEP LOOKING
FOR AN APPROACH,
BUT THE SPEED OF WHICH
THE ILLNESS HAS TRAVELED
MAKES IT DOUBLY DIFFICULT.
PERHAPS THE SURGEON GENERAL'S
OFFICE SHOULD BE ALERTED.
WELL, YOU KNOW
HEADQUARTERS, SPOCK.
THEY'RE ONLY
INTERESTED IN RESULTS
OF SPECIFIC TESTS.
SO FAR, ALL WE HAVE TO
OFFER ARE OUR OPINIONS.
ARE YOU SURE THAT
THE CAPTAIN WILL COMPLY
WITH YOUR ORDER IN
HIS PRESENT STATE OF MIND?
I'LL USE MY MEDICAL
AUTHORITY TO ENFORCE IT
IF NECESSARY.
DOCTOR, WE ARE TREADING
ON VERY THIN GROUND.
ACTIONS SUCH AS THESE
MIGHT BE MISINTERPRETED.
WELL, THEN SO BE IT.
OUR RESPONSIBILITY
IS CLEAR.
WHATEVER HAPPENED TO THE
CAPTAIN ON THAT PLANET
MUST HAVE TAKEN PLACE
IN THE SHORT
SPACE OF TIME
THAT HE WAS ALONE
WITH DR. LESTER.
PERHAPS A CONVERSATION
WITH HER MIGHT SHED
SOME LIGHT.
WELL, IT'S WORTH A TRY.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
TO GET TO DR. LESTER
WHILE I EXAMINE JIM?
WELL...GENTLEMEN.
I'M HERE, DOCTOR.
SPOCK, BONES, HELP ME.
DON'T LET THEM LOCK ME
AWAY FROM YOU.
I'VE GOT
TO TALK TO YOU--
McCoy: JIM!
SHE MIGHT
HAVE KILLED SOMEONE.
PUT HER IN ISOLATION
IN HER ROOM.
MAINTAIN
A 24-HOUR WATCH.
NO ONE, ABSOLUTELY NO ONE,
IS TO TALK TO HER
WITHOUT MY PERMISSION.
YES, SIR.
CAPTAIN.
HOW IS
THE DOCTOR?
SHE REGAINED
CONSCIOUSNESS
VERY QUICKLY.
GOOD. I HAVE
A FEW QUESTIONS
TO ASK HER.
DID THE CAPTAIN
ORDER IT, SIR?
WHY SHOULD HE?
THEY'RE
MY QUESTIONS,
THEREFORE I AM
ORDERING IT,
LIEUTENANT.
THE CAPTAIN SAID
THAT NO ONE IS ALLOWED
TO SPEAK TO DR. LESTER.
HAS SUCH
AN ORDER
EVER INCLUDED
HIS SENIOR
OFFICERS?
NO, SIR.
MR. SPOCK, I THINK
THE CAPTAIN MEANT
THAT A GUARD
SHOULD BE PRESENT.
BY ALL MEANS,
LIEUTENANT.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOUR HEART WILL LAST
FOREVER, CAPTAIN.
HOW AM I OTHERWISE?
IN THE PINK,
AS USUAL.
LIVER, KIDNEY,
BLOOD COUNT,
METABOLIC RATE.
EVERYTHING,
EVEN YOUR GLANDS,
FUNCTIONING
AT THEIR USUAL,
NORMAL PEAK
OF EFFICIENCY.
GOOD. I HOPE
YOU'RE AS PLEASED
ABOUT IT AS I AM.
DON'T GET DRESSED YET.
YOU SAID I WAS
IN PERFECT CONDITION.
PHYSICALLY.
I DON'T THINK
ANOTHER TEST IS
NECESSARY.
THE ROBBIANI
DERMAL OPTIC IS CRUCIAL.
IT REVEALS THE BASIC
EMOTIONAL STRUCTURE.
YOU HAD ONE ONCE BEFORE.
NOW I NEED ANOTHER ONE
TO COMPARE WITH THAT
PREVIOUS TEST.
THERE SHOULD BE NO CHANGE
IN YOUR DERMAL-OPTIC REACTIONS
TO THE COLOR WAVELENGTHS.
[DEVICE HUMMING]
OVER HERE, CAPTAIN.
COMPLETE
LIFE-ENTITY TRANSFER
WITH THE AID OF
A MECHANICAL DEVICE.
YES, THAT'S WHAT
IT MUST HAVE BEEN.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE,
SUCH TOTAL TRANSFER
HAS NEVER
BEEN ACCOMPLISHED
WITH COMPLETE SUCCESS
ANYWHERE IN THE GALAXY.
IT WAS ACCOMPLISHED AND
FORGOTTEN LONG AGO ON CAMUS II.
I AM A LIVING EXAMPLE.
THAT IS YOUR CLAIM.
AS YET, IT IS
UNSUBSTANTIATED
BY ANY...
EXTERNAL EVIDENCE
OR OBJECTIVE TESTS.
NEVERTHELESS, SPOCK,
IT IS THE TRUTH I'M SPEAKING.
[MACHINE PULSATING]
NOW LOWER YOUR ARMS
AND OPEN YOUR EYES.
AT THIS MOMENT,
DR. McCOY IS EXAMINING
THE CAPTAIN
FOR PSYCHOLOGICAL CHANGES.
IF ANY FACTS
ARE UNCOVERED,
THAT WOULD BE
ACCEPTABLE EVIDENCE,
THE ONLY KIND
WHICH IS ACCEPTABLE
TO STARFLEET COMMAND
AND TO THE CREW
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
SPOCK...
WHEN I WAS CAUGHT
IN THE INTERSPACE
OF THE THOLIAN SECTOR,
YOU RISKED YOUR LIFE
AND THE "ENTERPRISE"
TO GET ME BACK.
HELP ME GET BACK NOW.
WHEN THE VIANS
OF MINARA DEMANDED
THAT WE LET BONES DIE,
WE DIDN'T PERMIT IT.
THAT IS TRUE.
THE CAPTAIN DID NOT.
HOWEVER, THOSE EVENTS
HAVE BEEN RECORDED.
THEY COULD HAVE
BECOME KNOWN TO YOU.
YOU ARE CLOSER TO
THE CAPTAIN THAN ANYONE
IN THE UNIVERSE.
YOU KNOW HIS THOUGHTS.
WHAT DOES YOUR
TELEPATHIC MIND
TELL YOU NOW?
I BELIEVE YOU.
HOWEVER,
MY BELIEF IS NOT
ACCEPTABLE EVIDENCE.
EVIDENCE MUST BE
FACTUAL.
DR. McCOY
MAY BE OF HELP.
COME WITH ME.
I'M SORRY, SIR,
BUT DR. LESTER
CANNOT LEAVE HERE.
WELL, ARE YOU SATISFIED
WITH THE RESULTS
OF THE TESTS?
THERE IS NO
POSITIVE EVIDENCE
OF ANY DISORDER.
YOU'RE ASKING ME
TO VIOLATE
THE CAPTAIN'S ORDERS.
HE IS NOT
THE CAPTAIN.
YOU'RE AS MAD
AS SHE IS.
YOU'RE TO LEAVE
HERE AT ONCE.
I FOLLOW ORDERS.
CERTAINLY,
LIEUTENANT.
WE ALL MUST DO
OUR DUTY.
SECURITY GUARD!
NO HARD FEELINGS,
BONES.
YOU DID YOUR USUAL,
THOROUGH GOOD JOB.
[LAUGHS]
I'M SURE EVERYTHING'S
GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
[INTERCOM WHISTLES]
CAPTAIN KIRK.
CAPTAIN KIRK HERE.
ESCAPE ATTEMPT
BY DR. LESTER.
CAPTAIN KIRK TO SECURITY--
ON THE DOUBLE TO
DR. LESTER'S ROOM.
QUITE ALL RIGHT, ENSIGN.
EVERYTHING'S UNDER CONTROL.
PHASERS.
THE REPETITION OF
YOUR PHYSICAL VIOLENCE
IS NOT CALLED FOR...SIR.
Spock:
NO PHYSICAL RESISTANCE
WILL BE OFFERED.
ATTENTION, ALL PERSONNEL.
FIRST OFFICER SPOCK HAS
BEEN PLACED UNDER ARREST.
HE HAS CONSPIRED
WITH DR. LESTER
TO TAKE OVER THE SHIP
FROM YOUR CAPTAIN.
A HEARING WILL BE
IMMEDIATELY CONVENED
TO CONSIDER THE CHARGES
AND SPECIFICATIONS
OF A GENERAL COURT-MARTIAL
ON THE CHARGE...
OF MUTINY.
KIRK'S VOICE:
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 5930.3.
THE RESULTS OF
DR. MCCOY'S EXAMINATION
HAVE GIVEN ME COMPLETE
CONFIDENCE IN MYSELF.
MY FEARS ARE PAST.
I SHALL FUNCTION FREELY
AS THE CAPTAIN.
I AM THE CAPTAIN
OF THE "ENTERPRISE," IN FACT.
SURELY YOU MUST HAVE
MORE THAN THAT TO GO ON.
I HAVE STATED
MY EVIDENCE--
TELEPATHIC COMMUNICATION
WITH THE MIND OF
CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK.
YOUR EVIDENCE IS
COMPLETELY SUBJECTIVE.
WE HAVE TO HAVE EVIDENCE
THAT WE CAN EXAMINE
OUT IN THE OPEN.
SPOCK:
YOU'VE HAD A GREAT
DEAL OF EVIDENCE,
EXCEPT THAT OF
THE CHIEF WITNESS.
THE ONE WHO SHOULD
BE THE REAL SUBJECT
OF THIS INVESTIGATION
IS KEPT LOCKED AWAY
AND IN ISOLATION.
WHY...
CAPTAIN?
SHE'S DANGEROUSLY INSANE.
WE'VE SEEN THE EVIDENCE.
SHE IS DANGEROUS ONLY
TO YOUR AUTHORITY, SIR.
MR. SPOCK...
MR. SPOCK, MY AUTHORITY
HAS BEEN GIVEN TO ME
BY STARFLEET COMMAND,
AND ONLY
THAT HIGH AUTHORITY
CAN TAKE IT AWAY.
THE WITNESS, SIR.
BRING ON THE WITNESS.
LET YOUR OFFICERS PUT
THE QUESTIONS.
MR. LEMLI,
HAVE DR. JANICE LESTER
BROUGHT HERE.
AYE, SIR.
DR. MCCOY...
WHILE MR. SPOCK
WAS BUSY WITH
HIS AMBITIOUS PLOT,
WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
EXAMINING YOU.
OH, YES. YOU WERE
DEEPLY CONCERNED
ABOUT MY HEALTH,
EMOTIONAL
AND PHYSICAL,
SINCE LEAVING CAMUS II.
IS THAT CORRECT?
YES, THAT'S CORRECT.
AND INSTEAD OF TRYING
TO DESTROY ME,
YOU WERE SEARCHING
FOR WAYS TO HELP ME.
DR. MCCOY,
FOR THE RECORD,
WILL YOU TELL THE COURT
YOUR FINDINGS?
THE CAPTAIN IS IN THE BEST
OF PHYSICAL CONDITION.
HIS EMOTIONAL AND MENTAL
STATE IS COMPARABLE
TO THE TIME THAT
HE ASSUMED COMMAND
OF THE "ENTERPRISE."
THANK YOU, DR. MCCOY.
MR. SPOCK, WERE YOU AWARE
OF DR. MCCOY'S FINDINGS?
I KNOW THEM NOW.
AND WHAT HAVE YOU
TO SAY NOW?
I AM DISAPPOINTED
AND DEEPLY CONCERNED
THAT THERE IS NO
OBJECTIVE EVIDENCE TO
SUPPORT MY POSITION...
SO FAR.
[DOOR OPENS]
DR. COLEMAN,
IF YOU'RE REQUIRED HERE,
WE'LL CALL YOU.
WE CERTAINLY APPRECIATE
YOUR BEING HERE.
EVERYONE IS DEEPLY AWARE
THAT YOU HAVE BEEN
SUBJECTED TO INORDINATE
EMOTIONAL STRESS.
WE'D HOPED TO AVOID
ANY FURTHER STRESS,
BUT...MR. SPOCK
DISAGREES.
IT'S HIS OPINION
THAT YOUR TESTIMONY
IS IMPORTANT
IN DETERMINING
THE MERITS OF THIS CASE.
AND SINCE WE ARE SOLELY
INTERESTED IN ARRIVING
AT A JUST DECISION,
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO ASK YOU
A FEW MORE QUESTIONS.
I'LL TRY NOT TO UPSET YOU.
YOU, UH,
CLAIM THAT, UH...
[CHUCKLES]
THAT YOU ARE
CAPTAIN JAMES T. KIRK?
NO. I AM NOT
CAPTAIN KIRK.
THAT IS
VERY APPARENT.
I CLAIM THAT
WHATEVER IT IS THAT
MAKES JAMES KIRK
A LIVING BEING
SPECIAL TO HIMSELF
IS BEING HELD HERE
IN THIS BODY.
OH.
HOWEVER,
A-AS I UNDERSTAND IT...
I...AM DR. JANICE LESTER.
THAT'S VERY CLEVER,
BUT I DIDN'T SAY IT.
I SAID, THE BODY OF
JAMES KIRK IS BEING USED
BY DR. JANICE LESTER.
MM-HMM. SUBTLENESS
AND OBFUSCATION.
I ASSUME THAT THIS,
UH...
SWITCH WAS ARRIVED AT
BY MUTUAL AGREEMENT.
NO. IT WAS BROUGHT ABOUT
BY A VIOLENT ATTACK
BY DR. LESTER
AND THE USE OF EQUIPMENT
SHE DISCOVERED
ON CAMUS II.
VIOLENCE...
BY THE LADY...
PERPETRATED
ON CAPTAIN KIRK?
TSK TSK TSK.
I ASK THE ASSEMBLED
PERSONNEL TO LOOK
AT DR. JANICE LESTER
AND VISUALIZE
THAT HISTORIC MOMENT.
CAN YOU--CAN YOU TELL ME
WHY, UH, DR. JANICE LESTER
WOULD AGREE TO
THIS LUDICROUS EXCHANGE?
YES. TO GET
THE POWER SHE CRAVED,
TO ATTAIN A POSITION
SHE DOESN'T MERIT
BY TEMPERAMENT
OR TRAINING,
AND MOST OF ALL,
SHE WANTED TO
MURDER JAMES KIRK,
A MAN WHO ONCE
LOVED HER,
BUT HER INTENSE HATRED
OF HER OWN WOMANHOOD
MADE LIFE WITH HER
IMPOSSIBLE.
ARE YOU PREPARED
WITH WITNESSES?
ONE WILL DO.
SIR...
THERE IS ONLY
ONE ISSUE HERE.
IS THE STORY OF
LIFE-ENTITY TRANSFER
BELIEVABLE?
THIS CREW HAS BEEN
TO MANY PLACES
IN THE GALAXY.
THEY'VE BEEN
WITNESS TO MANY
STRANGE EVENTS.
THEY'RE TRAINED
TO KNOW
THAT WHAT SEEMS
TO BE IMPOSSIBLE
OFTEN IS POSSIBLE,
GIVEN THE SCIENTIFIC
ANALYSIS OF
THE PHENOMENON.
MM-HMM. AND, MR. SPOCK,
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD OF A CASE
SUCH AS DESCRIBED
BY DR. JANICE LESTER?
NOT PRECISELY, NO.
OH.
ASSUMING THAT YOU ARE
CORRECT IN YOUR BELIEF,
DO YOU EXPECT
STARFLEET COMMAND
TO PLACE THIS, UH...
THIS, UH, PERSON...
IN COMMAND
OF THE "ENTERPRISE"?
I EXPECT ONLY
TO REVEAL THE TRUTH.
AND WITH THE TRUTH
REVEALED THAT I AM
NOT REALLY THE CAPTAIN,
AND KNOWING THAT SHE
WOULD NOT BE ALLOWED
TO SERVE AS THE CAPTAIN,
THEN YOU WOULD
BE THE CAPTAIN!
IT IS INEVITABLE.
SPOCK...
SPOCK, GIVE IT UP.
RETURN TO
THE "ENTERPRISE" FAMILY.
ALL CHARGES
WILL BE DROPPED,
AND THE--THE MADNESS
THAT TEMPORARILY OVERCAME
ALL OF US ON CAMUS II
WILL FADE
AND BE FORGOTTEN.
AND WHAT WILL BECOME
OF DR. LESTER?
DR. LESTER WILL BE
CARED FOR, ALWAYS.
IT IS A DEBT
AND A RESPONSIBILITY
I OWE HER FROM THE PAST.
NO, SIR. I SHALL NOT
WITHDRAW A SINGLE CHARGE
THAT I HAVE MADE.
YOU ARE
NOT CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU HAVE RUTHLESSLY
APPROPRIATED HIS BODY,
BUT THE LIFE ENTITY
WITHIN YOU IS NOT
THAT OF CAPTAIN KIRK.
YOU DO NOT
BELONG IN CHARGE
OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
AND I SHALL
DO EVERYTHING IN
MY POWER AGAINST YOU.
LIEUTENANT LISA, PLAY BACK
THOSE LAST TWO SENTENCES
FROM MR. SPOCK'S TIRADE.
SPOCK ON TAPE: YOU DO NOT BELONG
IN CHARGE OF THE "ENTERPRISE,"
AND I SHALL DO EVERYTHING
IN MY POWER AGAINST YOU.
YOU HEARD THE STATEMENTS PLACED
INTO THE RECORD BY YOU.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THE NATURE OF IT?
I DO,
AND I STAND BY IT.
IT IS MUTINY!
DELIBERATE, VINDICTIVE,
INSANE AT ITS BASE!
BUT MUTINY AS CHARGED
AND ENCOURAGEMENT OF MUTINY!
DR. MCCOY, MR. SCOTT,
YOU HEARD IT.
ON THE BASIS
OF THESE STATEMENTS,
I CALL FOR
AN IMMEDIATE VOTE
BY THE POWERS GRANTED
TO ME AS CAPTAIN OF
THE "ENTERPRISE."
A RECESS IS DECLARED,
TO BE FOLLOWED BY A VOTE.
SPOCK: YES, SIR,
AN IMMEDIATE VOTE
BEFORE OUR CHIEF WITNESS
CAN BE LEFT TO DIE
ON SOME OBSCURE PLANET
WITH THE TRUTH LOCKED
AWAY INSIDE OF HER.
SILENCE!
YOU WILL BE SILENT!
A RECESS HAS BEEN DECLARED.
THERE WILL BE NO
CROSS DISCUSSION.
WHEN I RETURN,
WE WILL VOTE ON
THE CHARGE OF MUTINY.
THE EVIDENCE PRESENTED HERE
IS THE ONLY BASIS
OF YOUR DECISION.
SCOTTY.
DOCTOR.
DOCTOR...
I'VE SEEN THE CAPTAIN
FEVERISH,
SICK, DRUNK,
DELIRIOUS, TERRIFIED,
OVERJOYED, BOILING MAD.
BUT UP TO NOW,
I HAVE NEVER SEEN HIM
RED-FACED WITH HYSTERIA.
I KNOW HOW
I'M GOING TO VOTE.
I'VE BEEN THROUGH THIS
WITH SPOCK.
HE'S NOT BEING SCIENTIFIC,
AND NEITHER ARE YOU.
IT MAY NOT BE SCIENTIFIC,
BUT IF MR. SPOCK
THINKS IT HAPPENED,
THEN IT MUST BE LOGICAL.
DON'T YOU THINK
I KNOW THAT?
MY TESTS SHOW
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH THE CAPTAIN.
NOW, THAT'S THE ONLY FACT
STARFLEET'S GOING
TO BE INTERESTED IN.
HEADQUARTERS HAS ITS PROBLEMS,
AND WE HAVE OURS...
AND RIGHT NOW,
THE CAPTAIN OF THE "ENTERPRISE"
IS OUR PROBLEM.
THEY'RE GOING TO CALL FOR
THE VOTE IN A FEW MINUTES.
LET ME PUT
ONE LAST QUESTION.
SUPPOSE YOU VOTE WITH ME
IN FAVOR OF SPOCK.
THAT MEANS TWO VOTES TO ONE
AND SPOCK IS FREE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE CAPTAIN WILL DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU KNOW, ALL RIGHT.
IT'LL STICK IN HIS CRAW.
HE'LL NEVER ACCEPT IT.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
I'LL TELL YOU, HE WON'T.
THEN, DOCTOR,
THAT'S THE TIME
WE MOVE AGAINST HIM.
WE'LL HAVE TO
TAKE OVER THE SHIP.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
MUTINY, SCOTTY.
AYE.
ARE YOU READY FOR THE VOTE?
YES.
I'M READY FOR THE VOTE.
PLAY THE TAPES
OF THE CONVERSATION
IN THE CORRIDOR.
AYE, SIR.
SCOTT ON TAPE:
THEN'S THE TIME
WE MOVE AGAINST HIM.
WE'LL HAVE TO
TAKE OVER THE SHIP.
MCCOY ON TAPE:
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
MUTINY, SCOTTY.
SCOTT ON TAPE: AYE.
ARE YOU READY FOR THE VOTE?
THAT'S ENOUGH.
WE KNOW WHAT WAS SAID.
ENOUGH TO CONVICT YOU
OF CONSPIRACY
WITH MUTINEERS,
AND YOU'RE SO CHARGED.
THE SENTENCE--DEATH.
MR. LEMLI.
CHEKOV: STARFLEET
EXPRESSLY FORBIDS
THE DEATH PENALTY.
ALL MY SENIOR OFFICERS
TURNING AGAINST ME?
THE DEATH PENALTY
IS FORBIDDEN.
THERE'S ONLY
ONE EXCEPTION.
GENERAL ORDER 4,
AND IT HAS NOT
BEEN VIOLATED
BY ANY OFFICER
ON THE "ENTERPRISE."
I AM RESPONSIBLE.
EXECUTION WILL BE IMMEDIATE.
GO TO YOUR POSTS.
SINELLI, TAKE THEM
TO THE BRIG.
PREPARE FOR EXECUTION.
GO ON!
CAPTAIN REALLY MUST
BE GOING MAD
IF HE THINKS
HE CAN GET AWAY
WITH AN EXECUTION.
CAPTAIN KIRK WOULDN'T
ORDER AN EXECUTION
EVEN IF HE WERE GOING MAD.
THAT CANNOT BE
THE CAPTAIN.
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES IT MAKE WHO HE IS?
ARE WE GOING TO
ALLOW AN EXECUTION
TO TAKE PLACE?
IF SECURITY BACKS HIM UP,
HOW WILL WE FIGHT HIM?
I'LL FIGHT THEM
EVERY WAY
AND ANY WAY I CAN.
LIEUTENANT LISA, INFORM
ALL SECTORS OF MY DECISION.
HAVE EACH SECTION SEND
A REPRESENTATIVE
TO THE PLACE OF EXECUTION
ON THE HANGAR DECK.
MR. CHEKOV, HOW FAR
TO THE BENECIA COLONY?
COMING WITHIN
SCANNING RANGE.
PLOT COORDINATES
FOR ORBIT.
MR. SULU, LOCK INTO
COORDINATES AS SOON AS
ORBIT IS ACCOMPLISHED.
INTERMENT WILL
TAKE PLACE ON BENECIA.
YOU HAVE RECEIVED
YOUR ORDERS.
YOU WILL OBEY MY ORDERS!
OR YOU'LL BE CHARGED
WITH MUTINY.
YOU WILL OBEY
MY ORDERS OR...OR...
OHH.
FOR A MOMENT, I THOUGHT
I WAS UP ON THE BRIDGE.
SPOCK: PERHAPS YOU WERE.
THEN IT'S POSSIBLE
THE TRANSFERENCE
CAN BE BROKEN.
WELL, IF IT HAPPENS
AGAIN, I'LL FIGHT
TO STAY THERE.
THE BRIDGE
IS WHERE YOU BELONG.
TO ACCOMPLISH THAT,
EACH ONE OF US MUST BE READY
TO SEIZE ANY OPPORTUNITY
TO BREAK OUT OF HERE
AND ATTACK.
ARTHUR, THE TRANSFERENCE
IS WEAKENING.
WHAT HAPPENED?
FOR A MOMENT, I FOUND MYSELF
BACK WITH THE PRISONERS.
I WILL NOT GO BACK
TO BEING JANICE LESTER.
YOU MUST HELP ME
PREVENT IT.
THE ONLY WAY
TO PREVENT
THE TRANSFERENCE
IS BY THE DEATH
OF JANICE LESTER.
YOU MUST CARRY OUT
THE EXECUTION.
I CAN'T.
THE CREW IS IN MUTINY.
YOU MUST KILL HER
FOR ME.
I HAVE DONE
EVERYTHING ELSE
FOR YOU...
BUT I WILL NOT
MURDER FOR YOU.
THEN DO IT
FOR YOURSELF.
IF KIRK DOESN'T DIE...
WE'LL BOTH BE EXPOSED
AS MURDERERS.
DOES THAT GIVE YOU
ANY CHOICE?
THE DOSAGE SHOULD BE
DOUBLY LETHAL.
IT IS.
TO PREVENT ANY FURTHER
CONSPIRACY, YOU'LL BE
REMOVED TO SEPARATE CELLS.
IF THERE'S
ANY RESISTANCE,
YOU'LL BE GIVEN
A SEDATIVE UNTIL
YOU LEARN COOPERATION.
DR. LESTER
WILL BE FIRST.
FOLLOW DR. COLEMAN.
MAY I POINT OUT, CAPTAIN--
[COLEMAN STRUGGLING]
KILL HIM!
OH!
I'VE LOST TO THE CAPTAIN!
I'VE LOST
TO JAMES KIRK!
I WANT YOU DEAD!
I WANT YOU
DEAD!
[LESTER SOBBING]
OHH...I'M NEVER GONNA BE
THE CAPTAIN.
NEVER!
KILL HIM...OH...
[SOBS]
YOU ARE...
YOU ARE
AS I LOVED YOU.
KILL HIM.
CAN YOU DO
ANYTHING FOR HER?
I'D LIKE
TO TAKE CARE OF HER.
[LESTER SOBBING]
OF COURSE.
COME WITH ME.
I DIDN'T WANT
TO DESTROY HER.
I'M SURE WE ALL
UNDERSTAND THAT,
CAPTAIN.
HER LIFE COULD
HAVE BEEN AS RICH
AS ANY WOMAN'S,
IF ONLY...
IF ONLY.