So, Aristotle was Plato's student.
And Aristotle believes
that your character is voluntary,
because it's just the result
of your actions,
which are under your control.
For example, right now,
you have made the insane choice
to ignore the person
who is literally trying to
save you from eternal damnation.
No, yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm listening.
Uh, I just...
Are we sure we should be paying
attention to these guys?
It's like, who died and left Aristotle
in charge of ethics?
Plato.
[knock on door]
Uh, coming!
Uh, we're just... Kissing.
-And groping?
-[softly] What?
Hello.
Tahani. Hi. What brings you here?
You know, I was just, uh,
in the neighborhood. [laughs]
Do you get it, Eleanor?
Because, you know,
we're all in the same afterlife,
so, you know,
I'm always in the neighborhood.
Do you get it?
I do, and it's delightful.
Anyway, this is for you.
Just a housewarming plant.
It's a little reminder that
if there's ever anything that you need,
I am right next door.
How could I possibly forget?
-Have a great day, Tahani!
-Oh, all right.
[door slams]
Ugh. Tahani.
[in British accent]
Welcome to the neighborhood.
Even though we all arrived here
at the same time.
Here's some dirt I put in a bowl
because I'm amazing.
[slams]
I thought it was kind of a nice gesture.
[in normal voice] Oh, Chidi.
It's a total con.
I see through her little act.
Her act of being a nice person
who brings you gifts?
-Bingo.
-Okay.
I'll... I'll remind you
that you're trying to learn
-how to be a good person.
-Mmm-hmm.
Maybe you should return the favor
and bring her something.
Oh, so now I'm supposed
to be nice and make friends
and treat her with mutual respect?
Yeah.
That's exactly what she wants
me to do, Chidi.
Wake up!
That, that's what everyone
wants everyone to do.
Hello, Chidi.
No frozen yogurt for you this morning?
Oh, uh, no, just, uh, doing some reading.
Ugh, been there, brother.
Workin' hard or hardly workin',
am I right?
-Hump day.
-Uh, sorry.
Janet's functioning as my assistant,
but she's a little stiff, so I've been
trying to get her
to be a little more casual
and conversational.
-I'll have what she's having.
-It's a work in progress.
Listen, Chidi.
I've been studying your file.
You're a very interesting case.
You essentially only did one thing
while you were on Earth.
You thought and wrote about ethics.
Yes, I spent 18 years
working on my manuscript called,
-Who We Are and Who We Are Not...
-Right. No, no, no.
Practical Ethics and Their Application
in the Modern World; A Treatise on--
Yes, yes, yes, that's the one.
-That's the one.
-Mmm-hmm.
I think you should experience
new adventures.
You know, do things that you
haven't done on Earth, right?
So why don't we meet tomorrow
and try out some new hobbies.
Uh, why not? [chuckles softly]
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
Not if I see you first.
Where's the beef?
-[chuckles] I don't know.
-[Janet] Hump day.
[knocking]
Hello, Eleanor.
Jianyu, darling, look,
it's Eleanor from next door.
Is he asleep?
Yeah, there's really no way to tell.
Come on in.
What brings you to our home, my dear?
Well, I'm simply repaying your kind gift
with a housewarming gift of my own.
Fresh pears.
It's a plant, just like your gift,
but you can actually eat them.
So maybe it's a better gift.
-Who's to say?
-That's so kind.
However, in, um, Chinese culture,
pears are actually a symbol of bad luck.
And I wouldn't want to offend Jianyu,
so I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to throw these in the garbage.
But do come and sit down.
We haven't even had a chance
to discuss all of the mayhem
in our neighborhood yet.
-It's so disconcerting.
-Yes.
What do you think is causing it?
Oh, I'm sure I don't know.
But we must keep our heads up.
In fact, tomorrow
I'm actually going door-to-door
to make sure that every single person
in this entire neighborhood
is keeping calm and carrying on.
'Cause I think that helping
others will make me feel
like I truly belong here, you know?
Here's a brainstorm,
why don't I go with you?
I mean, I would love to do
my part to help the neighborhood,
not to mention, get a little
bonding time with you, lady.
Oh, hurrah!
[Tahani] Such fun.
[Eleanor] I'm telling you,
Tahani's out to get me.
[stammers] What are you talking about?
This note was slipped
under my door yesterday.
It has to be Tahani.
She just said to me... [in British accent]
"I want to feel like I truly belong here."
Well, where have I seen
the word "belong" recently?
Oh, yeah, kaplow!
I really don't think she's the type
of person who would write this.
She is that kind of person
and she did write it.
She wants everybody to think
she's such a perfect princess
just 'cause she's tall and glamorous
and has cappuccino skin
and curves everywhere.
And now I'm complimenting her.
And kind of turned on.
The point is, she straight up sucks, bro.
[chiming and rustling]
Whoa.
Typical Tahani.
Brings us a faulty plant so she can brag
about being a better gardener.
No, I think this is another way in which
your negative actions affect this world.
This plant represents
your relationship to Tahani,
so when you're mean to her,
it starts to wilt.
Well, then this plant is doomed
because tomorrow, I'm going with her
and I'm gonna prove to you
and to everyone that she is
secretly a two-faced,
calculating, phony bench.
-[whining]
-Hmm. Yeah.
Truth hurts, doesn't it, plant?
So, all I want to do is just check in,
see how everyone's holding up.
Just bring some cheer
to these extraordinary people.
Cool.
So, tell me about yourself.
I mean, I want to hear it all, girlfriend.
The good, the bad, the really bad,
the embarrassing,
the humiliating, just... Let's bond.
Okay, well I was born in Pakistan,
raised in London, schooled in Paris,
but I think the primary reason
that I'm in The Good Place
is that I raised quite a lot of money
for non-profit groups.
Oh.
Did you ever, uh, skim a little
off the top for yourself?
Gracious, no, no!
Every penny was accounted for.
And as I raised nearly $60,000,000,000,
there was quite a lot of pennies.
[chuckles]
But I also dabbled
in some other professions.
I was a model, a museum curator,
an "It Girl," and...
Oh, I was Baz Luhrmann's muse for a while.
That was quite fun.
Modeling? That's a crazy life.
Want to tell me about that
rock bottom you probably hit?
Oh, I didn't really do it for long.
Couture just doesn't fit my body.
I'm cursed with ample bosom.
And yet you soldier on.
Oh, this is silly...
So "Tahani" means
"congratulations" in Arabic.
And "Al-Jamil" means "beautiful,"
-so my full name altogether means...
-"Congratulations, Beautiful."
Thanks, Eleanor. You big flirt. [giggles]
[coin clinks]
-Hey, babe, got you coffee.
-Oh, great.
Oh, Andy's Coffee, uh,
we shouldn't go there.
Everybody's boycotting.
Yeah, I know that one guy
found a scorpion in his latte.
I don't really care, though,
'cause it's so close to here.
No, no, no, it's because
he's sexually harassing people.
Look, a journalist went
undercover for an interview
and recorded him. Here, watch.
Here's the thing, sweetheart.
You're very qualified,
but you're also what we call
in the coffee shop game a, uh, dog-face.
You're a three, and you have
to be a nine to work here.
It's just math.
-[woman] So, I didn't get the job?
-[chuckles]
No, dog-face, you didn't get the job.
All right, I'll check your references.
-Just to be nice--
-[woman] Hey, my breasts!
I'll check 'em. Oh, they're good. Honk!
I mean, this guy's a monster,
we can't support this guy.
Okay, hey, you're not better than me
just 'cause you won't support
a guy who grabbed a boob once.
No, I'm just saying we shouldn't go there.
We can get coffee somewhere else.
Did you know your left reference
is a little bit bigger
than your right reference?
It's not a bad thing,
it's just... It's a thing. [chuckles]
This is the perfect hobby for you, Chidi.
Cartography.
Your neighborhood stretches way beyond
what you've already seen.
And you can map it,
revealing all of the mysteries,
like an explorer.
-I see how that might be fun.
-[chuckles]
Uh, but, uh, exploring makes me nervous.
I have what doctors call,
"directional insanity."
I once got lost on an escalator.
So, not exactly Christopher Columbus.
Fun fact, Columbus is in The Bad Place
because of all the raping,
slave trade, and genocide.
The fact that it makes you nervous
is exactly why you should do it.
You know, get out of your comfort zone.
Become a trail-blazer.
Fun fact, all deceased members
of the Portland Trail Blazers
basketball team are also in The Bad Place.
-[giggles]
-Uh, yeah, sorry about this.
I steered her away from colloquialisms
and into "fun facts" and "trivia tidbits."
I thought it'd be more in her wheelhouse.
Fun fact, a "wheelhouse"
is a part of a boat.
Okay, thank you, Janet, thank you.
Fun fact, Janet is me.
All right, let's forget about exploring.
Plenty more ideas for hobbies.
-Let's walk back to town, shall we?
-Okay.
[Chidi grunts]
-Wrong way.
-[Chidi] Yep.
Well, Glenn, we just wanted to
make sure you were all right.
-Tahani, you're too sweet.
-Oh.
-Isn't she just the nicest person?
-Mmm-hmm.
That is what a lot of people are saying.
Oh, everyone I know is saying that.
Yeah, it's just a big neighborhood,
full of enormous mansions
and people who love Tahani!
[both laughing]
Eleanor and I just want to see
if there's anything we can do to help you.
Oh, Tahani, you are so thoughtful.
Despite all the chaos earlier,
we simply couldn't be happier.
Oh, I'm so glad to hear it, Cualli.
Please take a maple butter scone.
I made them fresh this morning.
Oh, they look a bit burned.
But they're not.
Hmm. Oh, fork, that's good.
Extra, extra!
Read all about you.
Chidi, this is the perfect hobby
for you. Journalism.
Well, obviously, I like to write.
But I don't love deadlines.
I prefer to take my time with things.
Yes, I know. Uh, you never even
named your dog, did you?
When it ran away, you posted signs saying,
"Responds to long pauses."
Look, Chidi, I'm just trying to
find you a hobby--
The hat--
That will bring you a positive experience.
What do you say?
I'm loving that hat on you.
It would look even better on my floor.
What is happening now?
I suggested she be friendlier,
she seems to have
slipped right into overt sexuality.
I got something you can slip into.
-Oh--
-Janet, no!
No, Janet.
Oh, Jianyu, darling,
would you like some tea?
That nod meant no, apparently.
Well, it was nice to get out and meet
all of our wonderful neighbors.
They all truly belong here.
Oh, yes, they do, cutie-pants. Boop!
Well, I should really be going.
I have to begin
my 12 step Korean skincare regiment,
but, uh, I'll see-- Oh, no, no, no.
Please stay and enjoy the evening tea.
I'll see you soon.
Boop!
"The Diary of Tahani Al-Jamil."
Okay. Arc welding.
You could learn sculpture,
you can make furniture,
you can get your hands
a little greasy, you know,
and you make things.
This equipment is very scary!
Don't be a baby. It can't hurt you.
Watch, I'll blowtorch your face off.
-Janet.
-Whatever.
This whole thing is stupid.
Oh, brother.
-I told her to be less flirty...
-[metal clanking]
And now she's cruel
and distant, apparently.
I just can't get this right.
Thank you for trying to find
me a new hobby.
Um, but I just want to be an academic.
I want to keep working on my manuscript.
Chidi, here's the thing.
See, I read your whole book,
all 3,600 pages of it.
It's, um... How shall I put this?
It's a mess, dude.
Hey!
She's right.
You see, Chidi, I can read the entirety
of the world's literature
in about an hour.
This took me two weeks to get through.
I mean, it's so convoluted,
I just kept reading
the same paragraph over and over again,
trying to figure out
what the heck you were saying.
-Oh, no.
-I mean, on page 1,000,
you start section two with the sentence,
"Of course, the exact opposite
might be true."
You're a brilliant guy, Chidi.
But you just kept revising and rewriting
and adding words to your title.
I think you just twisted
yourself up into a knot.
I have a very bad stomachache.
[Eleanor] Hey, man.
[door closes]
What's wrong?
Am I a good teacher?
Am I clear? Do I make sense?
Yeah, you're a great teacher.
I'm super ethical now.
-What's that?
-Hmm?
Nah, don't worry about it.
[sighs]
I stole Tahani's diary.
So I could see if her handwriting
matches the note
and also read about all the mean
and terrible things
she's definitely done,
so I can prove she's actually evil.
Huh.
What do you think that means?
You stole Tahani's diary.
I know I broke some ethical rule,
but I had good reason.
Eleanor, in order to be a good person,
you have to do good things.
And not stealing people's stuff,
that is just a basic kindergarten rule.
I mean, do I also have to
tell you to not throw sand?
First of all, throwing sand is
an excellent way to put out a vodka fire.
Why would you even know that?
Second of all,
I know that it may not be nice,
but neither is pretending to be
100% perfect, like Tahani does.
-She wrote that note.
-No, she didn't!
You did!
I was hoping you would come
to this conclusion on your own,
but, obviously, no one here
would ever threaten you.
That note is The Good Place
manifesting your own guilt.
Like with the plant,
or when you literally made
giant shrimp fly through the air.
I wrote myself the note.
And as it turns out, I do belong here.
Because I'm just as good as everyone else.
No, no, no. No, you don't belong here.
And in this place,
everyone is better than you.
It has been proven
by an infallible formula.
Tahani might be a little British
and condescending at times,
but she devoted her entire life
to helping other people.
She's a good person. Accept that.
Hey, babe.
Great news.
I got us tickets to the Coyotes game.
-Awesome!
-But, ooh, yikes.
Turns out two of the players have DUIs.
Guess we can't cheer for that team.
-Eleanor, I--
-You know what?
Instead, let's just stay in,
watch a Roman Polanski movie,
listen to R. Kelly,
and eat Chik-fil-A. Does that sound good?
There's bad stuff everywhere, man.
It's impossible to avoid.
Yeah, but shouldn't we just try?
Shouldn't we just try to do the
right thing whenever we can?
Why? It's so much harder
to live like that.
And it's not like someone's keeping score.
[sighs]
Look, I know you're gonna
break up with me, okay?
I'm not an idiot.
I read your emails to your dad.
Have fun being so amazing
and perfect until you die.
And by the way, I'm talking really fast
because I still go to Andy's Coffee,
and I got a full punch card, bro.
Good people make me insecure.
When I'm around someone
who I think is better than me,
I try and drag them down to my level.
That's why perfect Tahani
is like my kryptonite.
Well, even admitting that
is an important step.
And also, maybe don't listen to me.
I would love not to listen to you.
Wait, what?
Basically, my life's work
is 3,600 pages of garbage.
Even Michael couldn't understand it.
So?
-What does Michael know?
-Everything.
That's my point, he knows everything,
and it was too convoluted, even for him.
Michael does not know everything.
Michael does not know
I'm not supposed to be here.
You wrote 4,000 pages on one of the most
complicated subjects in the world.
I mean, I used to get bored
halfway through writing a text message.
Be proud.
[Chidi] I want to broaden my horizons
and try new things, and I will.
But even though I might have
gotten lost in the weeds,
I loved writing this book.
And I want to try again.
So, will you be my advisor?
Chidi, all I want is for you to be happy.
So if spending eternity
getting blunt feedback
on your circular, rambling ideas
will make you happy,
then of course I will be your advisor.
Let's throw that monstrosity
in the trash and start over.
Aren't there maybe
some parts worth salvaging?
Honestly, man, I don't even know.
I mean, that thing is unreadable.
I literally learned what headaches were
because that thing gave me a headache.
[clicks tongue] Okay.
There you go. New beginnings! Well done.
[Tahani crying]
Oh!
Oh, hello, Eleanor. Hi.
Sorry, I was just cleaning up.
Are you okay?
Do you want to talk about it?
Desperately.
It's Jianyu.
I just can't seem to connect with him.
I know that he took a vow of silence,
but he won't even talk to me,
his soul mate!
-And I adore talking.
-I know. You do.
Eleanor, you don't know
what it's like to be in paradise
and feel like there's something
just not quite right.
Well...
I may not know exactly
what you're feeling,
but I do understand.
And you deserve to be happy, because...
You are an impressive, thoughtful,
and special person.
Not to mention...
You have a rockin' bod.
[chuckles]
I mean, Jianyu may be mute,
but he's not blind.
-[laughs]
-You two belong here.
And you belong together.
And you have all of eternity,
so there's plenty of time
for things to change.
Oh, thank you.
I really needed to hear that. Come here.
Ugh, of course your hugs are amazing.
[yawns]
[yelps]
Stupid ledge. No stairs.
Everyone here is really into hugging.
Looks like someone learned something.
Well, it's 'cause someone else
is a really good teacher.
Eleanor, hello.
How are you, my dear, sweet bestie?
-[chuckles]
-Never better. What's up?
Well, Janet has been
acting as my assistant.
It's not what she was designed to do.
-Didn't go great.
-But now I'm back to normal.
It turns out that the best Janet
was the Janet that was
inside Janet all along.
She was feeling a little lost,
so I gave her
a self-help book
to restore her confidence.
Now I'm living my truth
and creating my bliss.
Anyway, um, look, Michael asked me
if I would serve as his assistant,
but I'd quite like to focus
on my relationship with Jianyu.
So I recommended
you for the job. [giggles]
Eleanor, you and I could work
side-by-side to figure out
what's going wrong with this neighborhood.
Will you help me?
-How could I say no?
-Yeah, hurrah!
-Hurrah!
-[laughs]
[sighing]
What now?
[sighs]
Relax, Eleanor.
[nervous chuckle]
You sent this to yourself.
This is your own guilt manifesting itself.
I've been waiting for you.
Jianyu? You talk now?
You sent me these threatening notes?
What the fork, man?
Some Buddhist monk you are.
You don't belong here. Admit it.
Okay, you're right. I don't belong here.
Michael made a mistake.
But I'm trying, dude.
I'm really trying to be a good person.
And I think I'm changing for the better,
so just please, please don't rat me out.
-Don't worry, I won't.
-[sighs]
Because I'm not
supposed to be here, either.
I don't know how I got here,
I have no idea what's going on,
and I am freakin' out, homie!
You got to help me. I'm scared!
What?