Hang on, hang on...
You're not supposed to be here either?
You're a mistake, just like me?
Yeah, and I'm freaking out, dog.
There's so much thoughts in my brain,
it's like my head is filled with rocks.
How have you managed to stay undiscovered?
Because I have had to dodge and weave
and barely escape with my life,
and you don't seem...
Like a super genius.
Hello, Jianyu. I'm Michael.
Before we start,
I know you were a Buddhist monk
and kept a vow of silence.
Would you prefer to remain silent
here as well?
You literally haven't said
a word since we got here?
Yeah. When I say I'm meditating,
I'm just trying to figure out
what the fork is happening.
I think we might be in an alien zoo
or on a prank show.
No, Jianyu, we're dead.
Oh, that's a dope prank. [exhales]
Got to give it up.
Okay, I need to make sure
that this isn't some sort of weird trap.
Is your real name Jianyu?
No. It's Jason Mendoza.
And by the way,
everyone here thinks I'm Taiwanese.
I'm Filipino. That's racist.
Heaven is so racist.
But Tahani said that you helped Michael
by putting your hand on his chest
and doing some sort of healing magic.
Yeah. A nurse did that
to calm me down once
when I crashed my Jet Ski into a manatee.
You crashed your Jet Ski into a manatee?
Yeah. I'm from Jacksonville, Florida.
It happens a lot.
What did you do for a living?
I was an amateur DJ specializing in EDM.
Electronic dance music.
I was also an amateur
hip-hop backup dancer,
an amateur body spray inventor...
Um, I did pranks on Vine.
None of those are jobs.
What did you do to make money?
Oh, I sold fake drugs to college kids.
Okay, good.
Okay, here's my biggest question,
how did you know
that I didn't belong here?
I figured it out the very first night,
at the party,
using my powers of deduction.
I heard you don't talk.
Well, here's something
for you to not talk about.
I don't belong here. [chuckles]
They made a mistake.
Total phony.
So... [shushing]
Okay, later, man.
Okay. I vaguely remember that.
I believe you, Jason.
You're not supposed to be here.
Welcome to the bottom of the barrel.
Hello, Tahani.
Oh, hello, Michael.
I was just picking out some fresh orchids
for my nightly orchid bath.
So, Tahani, one of your fellow residents
is opening a new restaurant tonight.
This neighborhood could use
a real morale boost.
And since you're an expert
at event planning,
I was hoping that you would help
with the grand opening.
Oh, Michael, say no more.
I wasn't going to. I was done.
Well, good, because, of course,
I will. Janet?
-Hey, there.
-Oh, hello, darling.
I would like to model tonight's event
on my most successful gala.
That would be 2006 fundraiser for stem
cell research in Barcelona.
"Barcelona," actually.
Oh, it was a perfect evening.
Princess Stephanie was there,
as were Posh and Becks.
You know, International
Sophisticate Magazine
gave us five Gwyneths.
[laughs]
Tonight, I'm going to select
my jauntiest suit,
and I may even wear suspenders.
It's one of the human clothing
items I'm most eager to try.
Oh, well, good luck.
Thank you. Yes, yes. I'm excited.
And a little nervous.
I'd say that I'm cautiously optimistic.
[laughs] I hope I don't chicken
out at the last second.
Sorry... We are talking
about suspenders, right?
Like... These?
You can do that with... Oh! I cannot wait.
Excellent.
[Eleanor] So, Tahani has no idea about me?
No. She thinks I'm a monk,
and she thinks you're her best friend.
Great. I mean, for us. It's a huge
bummer for her.
We need someplace
that we can talk in private.
I agree.
Let me show you my bud-hole.
What?
I should warn you, it's a little messy.
This is my bud-hole.
It's just, like, a hole
where me and my buds can hang out.
Oh, bud-hole! Okay, now I get it.
I wrote down on a piece of paper that
I needed a private meditation area.
Tahani will never come in.
Pretty unique decorating style
you have here, Jianyu.
It's like, "12-year-old boy"
meets "13-year-old boy."
Thanks. Janet helped me
get all this stuff.
She rules.
Is she single,
or is she married to Michael?
No, no, dude, you cannot date Janet.
A, she's not human.
And B, you have to keep
pretending to be Tahani's soul-mate.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Cool.
Okay, just sit tight, dude.
I have a class to get to.
What... A class?
I didn't know there were classes.
Chidi is trying to teach me
to be a good person.
And it's really hard.
Also, Michael has asked me
to be his assistant, whatever that means.
My whole situation here
is getting more and more dicey,
so I'm actually really glad
to have a place I can come
when I just want to be myself.
Yeah. I miss being myself.
Myself was the best.
[upbeat music playing]
What's up, man? You're Jason?
You got two minutes.
Fred Durst is throwing an orgy
on a partially capsized yacht.
My dad just texted. It already started.
So I'll get right to the point.
I listened to your demo.
You're terrible.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Okay? You just don't have any...
What's the word?
Talent.
But don't worry.
You got something better than talent, man.
You got my approximate size and weight.
I'm supposed to play this club
for the rest of the week,
but I just got an offer
to DJ Scott Disick's after party
for the Amateur Porn Awards in Reno.
Whoa, congrats, bro. That's the dream.
It's your dream, man. It's my Tuesday.
I just need somebody to fill in.
Put on the helmet.
Press spacebar on the computer.
Those idiots won't know the difference.
For the next week, Jason, you are Acidcat.
Whoa. There's a lot of old gum in here.
Tahani, how are things going
in the front of the house?
Because, to be perfectly frank,
things in the kitchen are
going great, okay?
I am right on schedule.
Chef Patricia, I have triple-checked
every single detail.
Your restaurant opening is going to be
the talk of the entire neighborhood.
Thank you for your thoughtfulness
and hard work.
I could not have done this without you.
[Michael] Ah, hello, Tahani.
Sorry. I should've warned you.
Patricia is actually very happy,
but she's also very intense.
It can be confusing.
No, no, no,
that's not what's bothering me.
It's just that, well,
I looked at the guest list earlier,
and Jianyu isn't invited.
Right.
Jianyu is a beautiful spirit,
but he literally doesn't talk,
and since this will be an evening
of lively conversation,
and you'll be busy working,
I didn't want him to feel uncomfortable.
I totally understand.
Well reasoned, Michael.
As us Brits are fond of saying,
"Try your best to hide your sadness."
So, the concept of the self
is a key subject
for a lot of great thinkers.
In the Tao Te Ching, Lao Tzu wrote,
"Knowing others is wisdom,
but knowing the self is enlightenment."
Ah... "Knowing" yourself.
Is he talking about
what I think he's talking about?
No, Eleanor. Once again,
none of these philosophers
is ever talking about masturbation.
Let's move on to this week's main event,
David Hume's A Treatise of Human Nature.
You read this, right?
I did. Well, I tried to.
Well, I tried to want to.
Mm, actually, could we
postpone this lesson?
I've befriended Jianyu from next door,
and I thought I could learn from him.
That's a great idea. Hume's
"bundle theory" of the self
is fairly close to Buddhism.
Yeah. No durr. That's why I'm doing it.
[music playing outdoors]
Do you hear music?
That's not music.
That's EDM.
What are you doing?
Eleanor, you were right.
No more pretending.
It's time for me to be myself.
What's up, homie?
Eleanor?
You broke Jianyu.
[sighs]
Okay, did we miss anything?
Oh! Take that jersey off, you goofball.
Okay. This is not my fault. I swear.
Eleanor, one hour ago,
that man was a silent Buddhist monk.
Right. But here's the thing,
Jianyu is actually...
A guy who is nice.
Hi, Tahani.
Eleanor, Chidi, What a lovely surprise.
Don't mind me. I'm just dropping off
my afternoon gloves,
and picking up my early evening gloves.
-How are you, soul-mate?
-I'm cool.
I'm sorry.
Am I going mad,
or did I just hear you say,
"I'm cool"?
Mm. Mm-hmm.
I don't think so.
I don't think that happened.
No, you're wrong.
I see what's going on here.
You've got a whisper in your snicker box.
You're both helping Jianyu
to regain his confidence
to be able to speak again
as a surprise for me!
Oh, busted.
[laughing] My heart is soaring.
[Michael] So, Jianyu is talking?
-Oh, how wonderful!
-[laughs]
I will do everything in my power
to encourage him.
Well, not everything.
I won't give him a second mouth.
Unless that would be helpful. No.
Better not risk it.
I've actually had a better idea.
Oh.
Let's add Jianyu to the guest list.
Chidi and Eleanor have been
working with him,
-and they're going to be here.
-What a great idea. Patricia!
We can fit another chair, right?
Change the floor plan
an hour before opening?
Of course! The more the merrier!
Oh, hurrah! [laughs]
I knew tonight was going to be perfect,
but now it's going to be even perfect-er.
Obviously, it's impossible for something
to be more perfect than perfect...
Well, it isn't, actually.
Any place or thing in the universe
can be up to 104% perfect.
That's how you got Beyonce.
Oh. [chuckles]
Oh...
Bud-hole.
Okay... Now, tell me everything.
[Eleanor] Okay, Jianyu...
Is a fraud, just like me.
His real name is Jason.
He's a drug-dealing DJ from Florida.
It's gonna be fine.
We just need a plan.
Oh, I got a plan.
We hack into Michael's phone,
download all his nudes,
and then blackmail him.
No. What are you... No.
Yo, you should listen to me.
I came up with hundreds of plans
in my life,
and only one of them got me killed.
[Eleanor] Dude, be quiet.
You are not Jason.
You are a monk named Jianyu.
Got it?
-[upbeat music playing]
-[crowd cheering]
[exclaiming]
Oh, another great set, Jason.
They love you, dude.
They don't love me, man.
They love Acidcat.
These cheers are fake.
They hit my ears
like boxing gloves of sadness.
Oh, that's some poetic thoughts, B.
I got to be myself.
Attention, Jacksonville. I'm not Acidcat.
I'm Mr. Music, the DJ.
And this is a Mr. Music, the DJ original.
[music playing]
[crowd booing]
[Jianyu groaning]
[glass clanking]
Welcome to the opening of The Good Plates.
[laughs]
I just got that.
-[crowd laughs]
-That's hilarious!
Anyway, at some point or another,
every resident in this neighborhood
will fulfill his or her soul's
true purpose.
Chef Patricia has done that tonight
by opening this restaurant.
[crowd applauding]
Now if you'd all like to take
a look at tonight's menus...
That's right. With Michael's help,
Chef Patricia has recreated
each person's favorite meal on Earth.
Fun!
[crowd applauding]
[overlapping gasps]
[indistinct chatter]
It's my Grandmother's maafe.
Fresh perch, slow-roasted
in a peanut sauce.
Almost makes me forget
how miserable I am right now.
You want to try a bite?
Fish and peanut butter?
No, I'm good. Thanks.
Tofu? Oh, man.
Imma order some jalapeno poppers.
[shushes] Be quiet
and eat your white sponge.
-Janet?
-Hi, there.
Hi. I didn't get a meal.
According to our files,
your favorite meal was
the hunger strike you went on
to protest Bolivian sex trafficking.
Oh, right. Of course I did that.
Tahani, great party. Check it out.
-Oh! [laughs]
-Suspenders! [laughs]
So dumb.
So much dumber than belts. [laughs]
Oh, congratulations, Michael.
How's Jianyu doing? Is he opening up?
Mm, not yet.
But I can tell he wants to.
Don't worry. I've got a plan.
May I have your attention, please?
Later this evening, we will be enjoying
Chef Patricia's delicious dessert,
a stunning three-tiered cake
that took her a full week to complete.
But first, I'd like to try something fun.
Each one of you has a very special memory
attached to the meal you're eating.
Why don't we go around the room
and share our stories?
Who'd like to begin?
[chuckles] I'll start, Michael.
[clears throat]
One day, I wasn't feeling so great,
so I made myself
a bowl of this chicken soup...
When it gets to you,
say something short and boring about tofu.
No. I'm sick of pretending
to be Jianyu, the tofu man.
I'm gonna tell the story
about my real favorite meal.
-Which is?
-The Buffalo wings
at Stupid Nick's Wing Dump in Gainesville.
Wings were free for ladies
if they took their top off.
Oh, boy. [clears throat]
-Chidi, a word?
-Yeah.
Anyway, that's how this simple soup
saved over 10,000 lives.
[Michael] Ah! Fabulous!
If Jianyu starts talking about
topless Buffalo wing restaurants,
we're all screwed.
[Michael] Jianyu Li, a Taiwanese monk
who took a vow of silence
at the age of eight
and hasn't spoken since,
is ready to share with us.
Let me tell you about Stupid Nick.
We need a distraction. Right the fork now!
No, no, no, no, no. [stutters] Eleanor?
Chef Patricia poured her heart
and soul into this.
Destroying it would be a truly cruel act.
Yeah, no durr.
-No, no, no! Oh!
-[sighs]
[crowd screaming]
[Micheal] Sinkhole! Everyone out!
There's a sinkhole!
[Glenn screaming]
Glenn!
You broke the world.
It's not a compliment!
-[screaming]
-[indistinct chatter]
Glenn, stay calm.
We're gonna get you out of there.
And we'll put your soup in the
fridge so it won't go to waste.
I know that may not be your number one
concern right now, but...
It was up there. It's real good soup.
Let's go.
Hey, buddy. You okay?
No.
I was just about to tell an awesome story
about a wing-eating contest that I lost,
and a barfing contest that I won,
but then a hole opened up in the ground.
I know. I made the hole
to save you from yourself.
You cannot let people know
who you really are.
It would be very, very bad.
[Pillboi] Beautiful,
beautiful Jacksonville.
What's wrong, dog?
You look like you're freaking out.
Things are bad, Pillboi.
Acidcat is suing me
for "bleach of contract."
I should have never pretended
to be someone else.
It could cost me all my dreams in life.
You got dreams in life? That's lit.
Of course I have dreams, man.
I don't want to be a DJ
in Jacksonville forever.
I want to DJ in Daytona, Tallahassee,
Tampa, even.
I want it all.
That's big goals, man.
I know, but I believe in myself.
Someday, the world will see
what I already know,
that Jason Mendoza
is a beautiful, unique soul
who has so much to give this world.
Okay, that's Acidcat's speedboat.
Hand me the thing that blows it up.
[indistinct yells]
Michael, I hereby tender my resignation.
I can no longer in good conscience
coordinate any further events
in The Good Place.
So, I am turning in my evening gloves.
-Tahani--
-Don't try to make me feel better.
The launch was a disaster.
Poor Jianyu was so terrified
that I fear he may never speak again.
My hair is barely cascading
down my shoulders.
Tahani, please.
I know your journey with Jianyu
has been frustrating,
but your situation is actually
very typical.
Soul mates sometimes take months
to really click.
You have to be patient.
And if anyone should take the blame
for the restaurant disaster, it's me.
I thought this neighborhood's
troubles were behind us.
Now I fear the worst.
Michael,
I hereby rescind
the tendering of my resignation.
We must keep the neighborhood together.
-What can I do?
-Oh,
well, the sinkhole should be repairing
itself in about three days.
Well, as soon as it does,
we shall re-launch the restaurant.
I'll hang posters to get the word out,
and in the meantime, I'll host
a brunch party every morning
to lift people's spirits.
-Ah!
-While you repair the universe,
I shall prepare the eggs.
Oh, fanciful wordplay.
Indeed. That is the Tahani
that you know and love.
-So what do we do here?
-There's nothing to do.
He's just gonna blab
and get him and me both sent
to The Bad Place.
It's hopeless.
[gunshot and explosions over TV]
I can't believe I'm doing this,
but, Jason,
please come to my classroom.
I will teach you ethics,
like I'm doing with Eleanor.
And if you work hard
and absorb the material,
you just might be able
to earn your place here.
No, I'm good.
[gunshots over TV]
Dude, Chidi is giving you
a lifeline right now,
and you need to take it because you suck.
-You suck!
-I know!
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
We both suck.
You know who doesn't suck? Chidi.
He is putting himself in danger
to help us,
because he, unlike us,
is an amazing person.
I didn't get into heaven to go to school.
You didn't get into heaven
at all, shirt-for-brains.
I just want to be myself.
That's a very, very bad idea.
Do not be yourself.
You need to be a better version
of yourself, okay?
And I do too. And our only hope right now
is this kind, selfless, amazing nerd.
Think about that.
[stutters] Do you have to call me
a nerd so much?
I said a lot of other nice things, okay?
Toughen up, nerd.
Let's get crackin', Teach.
I read this entire David Hume book,
and then I read it again
because I didn't understand it
the first time,
and now I'm ready to go.
Wow. Uh, that's really impressive.
Uh, where's Jianyu?
Honestly, I don't even know
if he's coming.
I am here to learn about ethnics.
[door bangs]
Wow! That's great, man! Um, I mean...
[stutters] It's ethics but that's great.
[whispers] Pretty sure it's "ethnics."
Hey, buddy, I'm proud of you.
This is your first step
towards not sucking.
Cool. I just have two questions.
When are football tryouts?
And does this school have a prom?
Oh, no.
Oh, wow.
For the first time ever,
I'm the smartest kid in class.
[building shudders]
[building creaking]
[gasps]