What are you doing?
Dude, I'm freaked out about
my meeting with Michael,
and if I spend one more second
staring at Creepo the Clown,
-I'm gonna lose it.
-You named the clowns?
Psycho, Creepo, Crazy Head,
Stupid Juggling Weirdo,
Freaky Feet, and Nightmare
George Washington.
One of them has to go.
Oh, sexy mailman. Much better.
In five minutes, Michael wants
my help investigating
what's making the neighborhood go nuts,
which is obviously me.
I mean, I did promise I would help.
What do I do here?
Actually, the answer is...
Right here, in this easily understandable
comic strip.
Nope, in this book about the theory
of contractualism.
What We Owe to Each Other.
[gasps] I saw this movie.
Laura Linney cries in a lake house
because Jude Law left
her for his ex-wife's ghost.
No. Quick summary of contractualism.
Uh, imagine a group of reasonable people
are coming up with the rules
for a new society.
Like, "If your Uber driver talks to you,
the ride should be free"?
Sure, but anyone can veto any rule
that they think is unfair.
So, if you said,
"We should be able to break our promises
without any repercussions,"
someone would veto that rule.
Well, my first rule would be
that no one can veto my rules.
Well, that's called "tyranny."
And it's generally frowned upon.
If you make a promise to someone,
you should do it.
Just like I promised to help
you and still am,
despite your constant mockery.
[mocking] "Despite your constant mockery."
Whatever, you love it.
So, either I help him find the problem,
which is me, and I'm doomed...
Or I don't help him,
and then I'm behaving unethically
and the whole world goes crazy
and I'm caught anyway.
I need to figure out a way
to both help him
and not help him at the same time.
-That's literally not possible.
-Oh, really?
I once posed as a hot prom date
for my cousin,
both helping him and later,
according to his therapist,
not helping him.
[Michael muttering indistinctly]
Oh, hey, Eleanor. Thanks for coming in.
Sorry about the mess.
[clears throat] Oh, I forgot,
you don't see in nine dimensions.
There's just a lot of...
There's a lot of tension
in the air right now.
Are you okay, buddy?
You seem kind of stressed.
No, no, no, I'm fine.
Top of my game, actually.
Um, here, let me just...
Have a seat. There you go.
So, to prepare to meet all of you,
I studied the human concept of friends.
I even watched all ten
seasons of the show Friends.
Boy, those Friends really were friends,
weren't they?
Although, and I realize
this is the kind of observation
that would only occur to the mind
of an eternal being...
How did they afford that apartment?
A waitress and a chef with those Manhattan
real estate prices.
Yeah, we were all confused about that too.
Anyway, it's been a tough couple of days.
Right now, I could really use a friend
by my side.
Well, you know me, the person who has
audibly promised to help you.
So, you need me to house-sit
the whole week?
Sounds like somebody's
gonna have a sweet vacay.
As I told you before, my mom is very sick.
I'm gonna help her move
into assisted living.
Well, I'm here for you.
And your Wi-Fi is way better
than my neighbor's, so I'm in.
It's gonna mean taking care of Lester too.
Walk and feed him twice a day,
-give him his kidney medicine.
-Yup, got it. Feed his kidneys.
-Eleanor...
-Yeah?
This is gonna be a very stressful
week for me.
-I need to know that I can count on you.
-I won't let you down.
I promise.
Jianyu, my love. How are you?
-I am decidedly so.
-That's very profound.
Um, soulmate. An idea.
Our neighborhood now features a spa,
and it offers couples packages.
And I thought maybe we could get facials,
and do yoga, and talk
in long, discursive sentences.
What do you say?
-Signs point to yes.
-Oh. [chuckles]
Marvelous! We'll go today.
Dude, you got to come with us to the spa.
No way. No, that's really weird.
You can't make small talk with her
for one day without being caught?
No, I can't. She freaks me out.
She's so pretty, like Nala
from The Lion King.
And she talks so smart,
like Nala from The Lion King.
You gotta help me.
Well, if I feel sympathy
for anyone, it's Tahani.
She's going through the same thing I am,
but she doesn't know it.
Which means maybe
I'm obligated to tell her.
Although, maybe it's better not to know.
Is ignorance bliss, or will the painful
truth actually be healing...
You ready, Jianyu?
Oh, I cannot wait to just relax,
and talk, and chat
and just, you know...
Get to know each other.
Hey! Maybe I'll come too.
Oh, well, Chidi...
It's just that this is, um...
This is really more of a couples thing.
I know.
But Eleanor's off with Michael, and Jianyu
feels comfortable when I'm around.
Right?
-Made in Taiwan.
-Yes, you were.
You were made in Taiwan.
So... Couples date!
Let's go!
I never really looked around
your office the first day.
What is all this junk?
Well, technically, architects aren't
allowed to own any human objects, but...
Oh, I just love them so much.
And over here, look at this.
Aren't paper clips the most
amazing things in the world?
Yeah. Sure.
Anyway, my current theory
is that some object
in the neighborhood is a design flaw
which is causing everything to go haywire.
So we need to find that object.
We're gonna start with the rocks.
Now, I've investigated all of the rocks
in the neighborhood.
These 78 are the most suspicious.
I mean, maybe to an architect
they might look suspicious,
but to me, they just look like rocks,
so I'm not sure how I can help.
Do any of them look defective?
Sinister? You know,
like they're taunting you?
Always one step ahead?
You devious little monsters, you.
Okay, let's take a deep
breath here, buddy.
You need to chill a little.
'Cause you have a very psycho,
"burnout guy muttering to himself
at a library computer" type vibe.
It's my responsibility to solve
the problem.
What else can I do except keep working?
You could stop working.
Look, I promised to help you,
and honestly, the way I can help you
is to force you to take a break.
And not working will help me work?
Yes! Recharge the old batteries.
I promise this is gonna help both of us.
Let's go.
Okay.
Let's keep our eyes peeled for twigs
that may have a nefarious agenda.
-Okay, crazy, come on.
-Yeah.
[Tahani] Hello, Janet.
Jianyu and I are here
for the couples package, please.
[clears throat]
And, also, I will be joining them.
Great, and who is the other half
of your couple?
Oh, no, no, it's just me.
Couples are pairs of people.
Yup, and, uh, there is a pair of people,
Tahani and Jianyu.
And then also I am here.
Great, and who will be joining you?
No one.
Um, it's really quite simple, Janet.
They are a couple,
and I am a third part of that couple,
a helper part who is here
for fun and excitement.
It's a three-person couple.
[in robotic voice]
Does not compute. Does not compute.
I'm just kidding. [laughs]
I mean, it doesn't compute,
but I'm not gonna explode or anything.
Right. Well, I'll see you inside, darling.
Okay, you have to step up.
Find a way to connect with her without,
you know, being you.
What does that even mean?
Do I talk or not talk?
Do I be nice to Tahani, or do I throw
all her jewelry in the toilet?
That's the opposite of being nice?
So no toilet?
What is it with you and frozen yogurt?
Have you not heard of ice cream?
Oh, sure, but I've come to really like
frozen yogurt.
There's something so human
about taking something great
and ruining it a little
so you can have more of it.
Ha! That is very human.
Why do you need a human
to be your assistant?
I mean, aren't there more of...
Whatever you are?
Well, since we're becoming friends,
like Ross and Phoebe...
Weird combo to pick, but okay.
I'm gonna tell you a secret.
Usually, architects don't live
in their neighborhoods.
Usually, the people show up,
we play the movie,
Janet is there to answer questions,
and you're on your own.
But I had this theory.
I thought transition would be easier
if the architect were on-site
for at least the first 1,000 years or so.
That's why you've been so freaked out,
'cause your butt is on the line.
My boss thought I was nuts.
And if this neighborhood doesn't work,
I am in big trouble.
But more importantly,
I promised all of you
that you would be safe and happy.
And you just don't break a promise.
Unlike Ross, when he promised
Emily not to talk to Rachel.
Wow, you are really into that show.
You know something?
I feel better already.
Should we get back to work?
[exclaiming] The whole point is to stop
thinking about work and start having fun.
Now, what should we do first?
♪ I'm going out ♪
♪ In a blaze of glory ♪
♪ Lord, I never drew first ♪
♪ But I drew first blood ♪
♪ And I'm no one's son ♪
♪ So call me young gun... ♪
This is so interesting!
I mean, there's no point to it.
The images on the screen
relate to nothing.
Some time passed, and then it was over.
That's karaoke!
Oh, let's do it again.
Okay, my hands are heated
to the ideal 105 degrees.
Who would like to go first?
Oh, well, what if I go first,
and then perhaps Jianyu
could stand near me
and share some intimate
aspects of his life?
Or what if...
While Janet messages Tahani,
I massage Jianyu?
Jianyu, darling, let's discuss the arts.
I adore the impressionists.
Who's your favorite artist?
I mean, Pitbull changed the game--
Sorry, just working the oft-neglected
mandible area.
[muffled speaking]
[gasps]
Oh, man!
I didn't even want that thing.
Why am I trying to win it?
Because the machine says it's a prize.
[exclaiming excitedly]
[Michael] How many tickets do I get? Six?
-Is that all?
-Well, watch this.
[straining]
-Is that allowed?
-Not really.
But it is a time-honored tradition.
Say no more. I got it. I got it.
[whoops]
[applauding]
You know something?
As much as I've always
wanted to be around humans,
I think I've missed a big part
of what makes them wonderful.
Sometimes all you guys think about
is how you can have the most fun.
Exactly!
That was practically my mantra.
What's up, dong bait?
Ha-ha. Drop everything you're doing.
Rihanna is performing in Vegas.
I got tickets. We are road-tripping.
Oh, I can't!
I promised I'd house-sit one more day,
and I have to feed this stupid dog.
I'm sorry, does this dog smoke
blunts topless
on a yacht like a boss?
-'Cause that's how Ri-Ri do.
-That's a very good point.
This is floor seats in Vegas for Rihanna.
The booze is free there.
Do I really need to keep going?
Okay, this is dinner tonight,
breakfast tomorrow...
I have an idea.
This is in case of emergency.
Do not eat this unless it's an emergency.
Wow.
I'm ready to be a mom.
I'm having trouble
getting this mask to stick.
Yes, it's 'cause my
pores are just so small.
There's no way anything
could ever adhere to my skin.
It's a curse, really.
Jianyu, what are your pores like?
[sighing]
Janet, can you show me
to the sauna, please?
Dude, she's trying so hard,
and you're giving her nothing!
Just pick a fact that you know about her
and just muddle through.
She said she likes
impressionist paintings.
Impressionist paintings?
Okay, say no more.
No, no, no, I definitely
feel like I need to say more.
Jianyu...
-[chuckling]
-So would you say I helped you today?
Oh, so much.
I had fun,
I didn't think about my problems,
and I won this ugly yellow toddler,
which is one of the most
beautiful things I've ever seen.
Thank you so much.
All right, I'll see you tomorrow, friend.
You sure this is where
you want to be right now?
At the Tea for Two couples cafe?
There's no use avoiding it, Chidi.
I'm alone.
Jianyu and I have nothing in common.
I just want a soulmate.
Someone I can share my passions with,
someone who I can talk to about
the ethereal colors of a Degas.
I love Degas.
I took painting lessons as a kid,
and Degas was always my inspiration.
And do you like France as much as I do?
Well, they enslaved my country
for 300 years. So, no.
-But they have great museums.
-Yes.
Welcome to my cafe, you two.
We have a special on soulmate muffins.
Two for the price of zero.
Everything is free.
Oh, well, we're not soulmates.
-No. [laughs]
-We're just...
-Soul friends.
-[waitress] Oh.
[Eleanor] Hey, buddy.
I have all new fun stuff
for us to do today.
Eleanor, I have huge news.
Not working actually worked.
It did what now?
After our day off,
with a completely clear head,
I realized part of what makes humans
so fun is that they're unpredictable.
The chaos we've been experiencing
is exactly what would happen if a resident
behaved unpredictably.
The problem in our neighborhood,
it's not a rock or an object.
It's one of the people.
Oh! We need to celebrate.
I know, okay...
[exclaims]
Paper clip shower!
[laughing]
So do you think we're looking for a man,
or do you think we're looking for two men?
Not sure.
We don't know anything about this person.
I mean, does he or she even know
that they caused all these problems?
No, that can't be.
I mean, what kind of monster would
wreak havoc and then say nothing?
So this is the main place
where the garbage fell from the sky.
-Janet.
-Hi there.
I need a list of everyone
that was here on garbage duty
during orientation.
Oh...
Eleanor, our criminal
is on this very short list.
People were flying that day too.
I'll add everybody who flew overhead.
[groans in frustration]
Eleanor, our criminal is
on this much longer list.
[sighs]
[engine revving on game]
Oh, hey, homey. Thanks for your advice.
I'm about to give Tahani
the best gift ever.
Check it.
What?
She likes impressionist paintings, right?
I got her a painting of the best
impressionist of all time,
Frank Caliendo.
He can do it all. Fat Al Pacino,
fat Jerry Seinfeld,
regular John Madden.
"Say hello to my little friend.
Forget about it."
This is where the sinkhole opened up.
And the guest list that night was limited.
There were a total
of 30 people here that night.
-[exclaiming in delight]
-Only 30, huh?
Yeah! How do you pump your fist again?
Is this it?
But, 66 others passed through
to take a look before it opened,
and everyone else in the neighborhood
was in a close radius.
Oh, boy, that...
Doesn't narrow it down at all.
Feels like the end of the road.
End of the Road, Boyz II Men, karaoke.
Let's go. Don't think about it too much.
Janet.
My hoodie, please.
-What's happening?
-I give up.
I can't help the people
I promised that I would help.
I feel like Friends in Season 8,
out of ideas and forcing
Joey and Rachel together,
even though it made no sense.
I hope the sinkhole opens up again
and swallows me whole.
Paula! Hey, girl. How's the dog?
Still fat, Eleanor. Still fat.
The vet says his stomach expanded
to the size of a basketball
and that it will never shrink.
Oh, well, that's not my fault.
How was I supposed to know he would
literally eat all of the food?
It shouldn't have been an issue.
You were supposed to be there,
but you broke your promise
as soon as it wasn't convenient for you,
and now I have a very bulbous dog.
Well, you know what? You're rude.
'Cause you didn't even ask me
how the Rihanna concert was.
She was very late. And a little drunk.
I promised to help you, and I will,
however I can.
If you want to look at a million rocks
like a psychopath, I'll be there.
If you want to just lay here
and cry in your hoodie,
I'm cool with that.
Honestly, I don't know how I can help you,
'cause I'm just a person and you're, like,
this super-magical
Orville Redenbacher-type guy
who invented this entire universe,
but I'll do my best.
I'm right here.
Oh, my gosh.
Of course.
How did I not see it?
Janet...
I found the answer to the problem.
Call a neighborhood meeting.
Should it be festive and casual
or moribund and devastating?
Moribund and devastating, please.
Great!
Hello, Jianyu, Chidi.
What's this?
I made you a art.
It's three of me.
It's ballerinas,
painted in the style
of the impressionists.
Of course.
You don't say things, but you do things.
And you feel things.
Only my true soulmate could ever give
me such a perfect gift.
Thank you!
[indistinct chattering]
What's going on?
Well, I did what you said.
I honored my agreement to help Michael
find the problem,
and he found the problem.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
After I'm gone, take down
the rest of those clown paintings.
But leave up the sexy mailman.
To remember me by.
Thank you all for your patience
with the problems in our neighborhood.
I have finally discovered the cause.
There was one common
link among every incident.
And when I figured it out, it was a shock.
But there's no escaping it.
The problem...
Is me.
[all gasping]
And now, I have to leave you...
Forever.