[door opens]
Eleanor, come on in.
Well, not often you get to confront
your greatest failure face-to-face.
Good to see you, too, bud.
I am just dumbfounded
as to how this happened.
Our system has never
made a mistake before...
It's just not possible.
And yet, here we are.
First things first...
Who are you?
Well, my name is Eleanor Shellstrop,
and some of the info you had was right.
I mean, "flattened by boner pill truck
after dropping margarita mix
in grocery store parking lot,"
that's a very me way to die.
But all the other info was wrong.
In my defense, when I first arrived,
and you said,
"You, Eleanor Shellstrop, are dead,
and you're in The Good Place."
I had no reason to think
that was a mistake.
Location and date of birth, please.
Phoenix, Arizona, October 14th, 1986.
So sorry.
That's what I used to tell people
when I lied about my age.
I was born in 1982.
You lied so much,
you forgot your own birthday.
Not a great start,
but it should be enough
for Janet to locate your file.
-Janet?
-[tone chimes]
-Janet...
-What's that?
What's that?
[gasps] What's this?
Her memory's still being rebooted
because, oh, you know,
someone murdered her.
Janet, could you please locate the file
for an Eleanor Shellstrop, born in...
-1982?
-Yes.
Phoenix, Arizona, USA.
-Sure.
-[tone chimes]
Anything else?
No, Janet, this is actually a cactus.
This might take a while.
[Janet] Whee!
[sighs] Since Janet
can't retrieve your file,
I need to find another way
to determine what kind of person you were.
This is a quick litmus test.
Handful of questions designed to tell
whether you were fundamentally
good or bad.
Question number one.
Did you ever commit a serious crime,
such as murder, sexual harassment,
arson, or otherwise?
No.
Did you ever have
a vanity license plate,
like "Mama's BMW"
"Lexus for Liz" or "Boob guy"?
No.
Did you ever reheat fish
in an office microwave?
Ew, no.
Have you ever paid money to hear
music performed by California
funk rock band
The Red Hot Chili Peppers?
No.
Did you ever take off your shoes
and socks on a commercial airline?
And socks?
Ew, who would do that?
People who go to The Bad Place,
Eleanor, that's the point.
And unless I can figure out
a compelling reason to keep you here,
you will spend eternity with murderers,
and arsonists,
and people who take off their shoes
and socks on commercial airlines.
[clears throat] Janet, can I have
a glass of water, please?
-[tone chimes]
-Here you go.
Oh, gosh.
[chuckles] You said, "Water?"
-Yeah.
-I'm so sorry.
-[tone chimes]
-There you go.
Ah...
I really do have sympathy
for your situation.
I mean, you thought your soul mate
was a good person,
and then you learned that
she's just an immoral grifter.
-Tahani, please.
-Am I wrong?
She lied to everyone.
She caused a giant sinkhole
into which poor Glenn fell.
She caused a trash storm.
She... Well, she pretended to be my friend
when I really needed one.
And, lest we forget, she murdered Janet.
As far as I'm concerned,
the sooner she's gone,
the better off we'll all be.
I understand that Eleanor
violated our trust,
but please, when you're talking
to Michael,
try to think about what she's
had to go through.
All right. I will, for you.
But we've been through a lot as well.
You know, I haven't been this
upset since my good friend
Taylor was rudely upstaged
by my other friend, Kanye,
who was defending
my best friend, Beyonce.
And finally, a multi-part question.
Did you ever appear on the American
television program
The Bachelor or its companion shows,
The Bachelorette and Bachelor in Paradise,
or post on any social media site
that you were emotionally invested
in any of the relationships
the contestants were pursuing?
No.
Okay.
You did very well on the questionnaire,
Eleanor. So far, so good.
-[tone chimes]
-Michael, good news.
I was able to obtain
Eleanor Shellstrop's file.
[sighs] Is it actually a cactus?
I don't understand.
I want to see the file
for Eleanor Shellstrop.
Is that what you have,
or do you have a cactus?
-I have the file.
-You're sure?
You have the file and not a cactus?
That is correct.
I have Eleanor Shellstrop's file.
I do not have a cactus.
Excellent! Please, give me the file.
-Here you go.
-[tone chimes]
Thank you, Janet.
-You're welcome.
-[tone chimes]
Well, I say we call it a day.
I mean, I nailed the questionnaire,
and you're swimming in cacti.
Can't we just chalk this up to a hilarious
mistake and move on?
No, we can't, Eleanor.
There's no such thing
as a mistake in this realm.
And yet, you are, somehow, a mistake.
I mean, you're a giant chunk of spinach
in the teeth of the universe.
I need to understand every facet
of this disaster.
Tell me a lie about yourself.
Any lie.
I love the opera.
And now a truth.
I love Women's MMA.
We don't like to use this.
We've never really had a call for it
before you, but in the interest of time.
Eleanor, did you murder Janet?
No, I did not.
Do you know who did?
Yes.
Will you tell me who it was?
No.
I assume it was one of your friends,
and I admire you
for protecting him or her.
But, Eleanor, in The Good Place,
there's no room for bad people
or bad actions.
So anyone involved
in the murder of Janet
will be reviewed and judged,
and there will be consequences.
Tahani, come on in.
Chidi.
Impostor who soiled our paradise
with her moral turpitude.
'Sup?
Thank you for confessing, I don't know
what I would have done if you hadn't--
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm amazing.
Bad news.
Michael knows I didn't kill Janet,
which means it's only a matter of time
before he finds out that you did
and that you did it because you were
trying to stop Bonehead Jones over here.
Hey, homies!
Then he'll figure out that Jianyu's also
a phony, and, here's the real dong-buster,
Michael said anybody who did anything bad
might have to go...
Oh...
Which means Jianyu's gone,
you might be gone,
and all three of us are royally
forking forked!
This is terrible.
What am I supposed to do if he asks me?
I don't know. Kant would say that lying
in any scenario is wrong,
so if Michael asks you if you killed
Janet, you should say yes.
On the other hand,
snitches do get stitches.
That is true. I read that once
on the back of my boy Peanut's tricep.
You just casually cited Immanuel Kant.
Yeah, I know we're
in a miserable bind here,
but this might be the proudest
day of my life.
No offense, but that's
a real bummer of a life.
Tahani, I'll get right
to the crux of the matter.
Did you murder Janet?
Absolutely not.
Now, you spent a lot
of time with Eleanor.
Why do you think that is?
Well, people are just drawn to me.
You know, one of my shyest friends,
I won't say his name,
to preserve his privacy,
but he found my presence so comforting
that he asked me to co-host his TV show
Anderson Cooper 360.
Given what you learned about Eleanor,
do you think she deserves to be here?
Well...
You know, if it were up to me,
I might find a way to look past her, um...
Deficiencies.
But it's not up to me, is it?
There are some criteria
that she unfortunately
just didn't meet in her time on Earth.
So you think that I should
send her to The Bad Place?
Well, I didn't say that,
but is her staying here unfair
to those who earned their place?
It sounds like you want her to leave.
Well, is it not she who wants
us to leave her?
Thank you, Tahani.
You've been a big help.
Listen up, genius.
He's gonna call you in there in a second.
Don't worry, I got you.
I'll just tell Michael
you're the bomb and that you got
a dope soul and hella ethics.
Oh, boy.
No, don't say any of that.
Michael has a lie detector in there.
It's a glowing cube.
Like the AllSpark?
From Transformers?
Sure, just like the
AllSpark from Transformers,
and he'll know instantly
if you're lying about anything
so only smiles and nods, got it?
Wise, sage, centered Jianyu.
I seek your wisdom
in this moment of crisis.
What to do with Eleanor?
Should I let her stay?
Should I send her away?
You think I should send her away?
No, I should let her stay?
Or no, I shouldn't let her stay
because she doesn't belong here?
even though she does belong here?
Oh, Jianyu, I wish I had your wisdom.
Your devotion to the noble truths
has given you something
that I don't have, clarity.
It was Buddha who said,
"If a man lives a pure life.
"Nothing can destroy him."
I'm not a man, and I've lived no life,
so will this destroy me?
Ouch!
Oh, of course.
A cactus on its own intends no harm.
It's only when we interfere
that it becomes dangerous.
I need to remember my own agency here.
Oh, thank you, Jianyu.
You're free to go.
Oh, yes, of course. Help yourself.
I've got plenty of those.
Chidi, come on in.
-[tone chimes]
-Hi, there. I have Eleanor's file.
Janet, if you hand me a cactus,
-I swear I will lose my mind.
-[tone chimes]
Oh, yes!
All right, here we go.
Eleanor, come back in.
Chidi, you stay here.
[sighs]
This file contains a compendium
of all of the highest impact events
from your life.
That's the biggest positive
and negative point swings.
So "Little Julie," who's that?
Julie is my cousin's daughter.
Her mom is kind of a mess,
so I used to take her
to the mall sometimes
and bought her churro dogs.
It's a hot dog,
but the bun is two churros.
And it's tied together with a Slim Jim.
It's an Arizona delicacy.
Oh, sounds awful, but it's very nice
that you made that girl happy.
So what's this "Kool Threadz,
"Glendale, Arizona's
Premiere T-Shirt Emporium"?
Uh... Can we skip around and circle back?
How about I tell you more
about those churro dogs?
They came with unlimited ranch dressing.
Let's hear about the t-shirts, please.
[squeals] Okay.
I'll tell you,
but it doesn't make me look great,
so don't judge me.
That's literally the purpose
of this entire exercise.
Okay, to understand this,
you have to know
about my roommate, Madison.
She was terrible.
[Eleanor] Hey, Mads.
Um, I have to go to this
stupid work party tonight.
Can I borrow your peach dress?
Ooh, that's a hard no, babe.
That dress is like twice your salary.
All right, I gotta go to the DMV
and pick up my vanity plates.
Ciao, bitches.
[sighs]
[dress rips]
[sighs] Well, that's not great,
but I assume you confessed
and paid to fix it.
Not exactly.
Hey, losers, I'm going out.
Can you zip me?
Dude, that dress is hella ripped.
-What?
-[laughing]
Oh, that stupid dry cleaner!
Well, that's the risk you take
when you keep your clothes clean.
My mom's a lawyer.
Those asswipes are gonna pay.
She sued for $900 for the dress
and $80,000,000 in emotional distress.
The legal fees drove the dry cleaner
out of business.
Oh, boy.
Wait, this story's about t-shirts.
There's more, isn't there?
A little.
Check this out.
Somebody put the dry cleaners'
story online, and it went viral.
Madison's famous.
The "Dress Bitch"? Yikes.
[snickers] Serves her right.
Madison is psycho.
She totally overreacted.
This is her fault.
Yeah, her fault. That works.
[door opens]
You guys, what is happening?
Someone egged my Lexus,
and I have like 40,000 tweets
calling me the "Dress Bitch"?
Over a loser dry cleaner man?
Why is everyone so jealous of me?
This is a trash city, full of idiots.
-[laughing]
-[door closes]
-The "Dress Bitch" is so catchy.
-Yeah.
I mean, someone could
totally make t-shirts.
[gasps] Oh...
No, no. No. No.
Do not tell me that you made
t-shirts that said...
That and then sold them for a profit?
Wish I could tell you that, bud.
[sighs] I really do.
Girl, check it out!
They're here.
Wait a second. Is this insane?
I mean, should we be doing this?
Dude, Madison brought
this on herself, okay?
She's a nightmare of a person
to everybody.
Plus, we already have
a ton of pre-orders.
Here is your first cut of the profits.
Holy mama!
I can't believe you sold the t-shirts.
Does it help if they basically
sold themselves?
I think you know it does not.
What did you do with the money?
Yeah. [sighs] I was hoping
you wouldn't ask me that.
[beeping]
Thanks, babe.
Next question.
Eleanor.
Given what you know about the people
who've been brought here,
the lives they've led,
do you think you belong in The Good Place?
No, I don't.
[Trevor] Yello, Bad Place.
What's up, dummy?
This is Michael, the architect from
Good Place Neighborhood 12358W.
I'm guessing you've been looking
for someone called Eleanor Shellstrop.
She's here. Come and get her.
[train whistling]
[woman grunts]
[Alexis] What is this?
What is that smell? Ew.
[Good Place woman] Get out of here!
Hello, Trevor.
Hey, there he is.
Good to see you again, Mikey.
Hey, think fast,
I brought you something.
Oh, nuts, thank you. Oh!
[laughing]
Oh, flaming snake ate
all the nuts you brought me.
Argh. You're too nice to humiliate.
Oh, hello.
Hi, you look like a piece of crap,
are, are you Eleanor?
Dude, you're like
a legend in The Bad Place.
You're... Check this out.
-Huh?
-[all] "Dress Bitch"!
It's pretty great, right?
Trevor...
Do you know what caused this mistake?
'Cause I cannot figure it out.
No, we're stumped, but,
don't sweat it, champ.
She's definitely one of ours.
So we'll just roll on out,
and you can get back to,
putting rainbows up your butt
or whatever you do here. Okay?
[claps twice] Let's hit it, sweetheart.
We got a long ride.
What? Right now?
Trevor, for decency's sake,
let her have some good-byes.
[groans] God, good people are the worst.
Okay, uh, 30 minutes.
We gotta get back for The Bachelor.
I'm gonna be pissed
if I miss the Rose Ceremony.
I just want to say,
once more, for the record,
that this whole good/bad system
is bull-shirt.
There should be a medium place
for people like me
who kind of sucked,
but in, like, a fun, chill way.
I agree. [chuckles softly]
I'm sorry I dragged you into this.
And that I never did laundry.
And that I waited until you were
about to do yours
then secretly tossed mine
into the basket
to trick you into doing it.
You didn't trick me.
I repeatedly asked you to stop.
Just know you did everything
you could to help me.
You're a really good fake soul mate.
[knock at door]
What are you guys doing here?
Well, we only thought
it was only proper to see you off.
It's the neighborly thing to do.
You guys came to say good-bye
because you're my friends.
Well, I... Suppose some part of me
possibly has a sense
of casual kinship with you.
Much as one might be fond of a street cat.
Thanks, Tahani.
Sorry about everything.
I'm really glad we're friends.
Oh, hey, dum-dum.
You ready to go?
Oh, you must be Chidi.
Trying to improve her.
Bold plan, bro.
Well, actually, she learned a great deal
-in a very short amount of time--
-Oh, really? Really?
I don't care.
[claps] All right, let's hit it.
Oh, also, you should smile more.
You have such a pretty smile.
Love you, babe.
Can't wait to torture you.
This is the 3:18 to The Bad Place,
making thousands of stops
for literally no reason.
Now, you'll notice it's very hot in here,
and it will get one degree hotter
every time you think
about how hot it is.
Oops!
You just thought about it.
-Michael...
-Oh, hi, Chidi.
Want some pizza?
Bad Place crew delivered 100
of these to my office.
All Hawaiian, the worst pizza.
Michael, I murdered Janet.
I knew about Eleanor from the beginning.
I've been trying to help her
become a better person,
and when she found out
that your retirement meant
that you would be tortured,
she immediately tried
to find a way to prevent it.
Eleanor is learning.
She's just doing it after she died.
I did enjoy her company.
But, this is not Little League.
There is no award
for "Most Improved Player," Chidi.
Well, maybe there should be.
One final note, the dining car
is at the very back of the train.
It serves only room-temperature
Manhattan clam chowder,
and also, it's closed.
Okay, here we go.
-[Michael] Stop this train!
-[train squeals to a stop]
Dude, what the fork?
You're not leaving. Not with her.
Not yet. Come on.
[Trevor] Wait, you want to keep her?
Bro, that's our girl.
We agreed on this.
No, what we agreed on was
that this was a mistake.
Trevor, we're in unchartered
territory here.
Until we can sort this out,
she stays with us.
All right, fine,
but until this is resolved,
we're keeping the other Eleanor.
Fine. What? I'm sorry...
-The other Eleanor?
-Yeah, the real Eleanor.
The one that was supposed to be here
but got sent down to us instead?
She's on the train.
Eleanor, come on out.
Hi, everyone, I'm Eleanor Shellstrop.