-[indistinct chattering]
-[phones ringing]
[Dave] Morning, Mike. How's it hanging?
Oh. Fine, Dave, just fine.
Listen, we got the files
for the new crop of incoming,
and the Big Guy thinks it's time
for you to fly solo.
I get to design it myself?
You've been an apprentice long enough.
You're ready.
Oh, Dave, I'm gonna work so hard.
-My design is gonna be absolutely perfect.
-[chuckles] Easy there, rookie.
Starting immediately, you'll be reporting
directly to the front office.
This is your shot. Good luck.
[Shawn] The Bad Place is owed two people.
You have all done bad things
since you arrived here.
I don't care which two of you go.
You can decide.
You have 30 minutes.
[chimes]
[beeping]
All I ever wanted was
for this neighborhood,
my first neighborhood to be perfect.
Somehow I blew it and...
Well, you're all suffering,
and for that, I'm deeply sorry.
This is truly the saddest day of my life.
[merry music plays]
[theme music playing]
-[sighs]
-Okay, I guess I'll speak first.
Jason and I are the mistakes.
We're the ones who misled everybody
and dragged you all into this mess, so,
we should go to The Bad Place.
-Agreed.
-Yes.
Okay, I thought you were gonna at least
pretend to fight me on that, but whatever.
Hang on. That judge guy just said
everyone here has done bad things.
Let's look at this ethnically.
-"Ethically."
-You guys helped me and Eleanor, right,
but we're bad, so you helping us was bad.
It's basic consequentialism,
the morality of an action
is solely judged on its consequences.
Great. [chuckles]
The one time you actually
remember something from class.
Maybe I was brought here by mistake,
but since we've been here,
I just tried to stay
out of everyone's way.
Chidi's done worse stuff than me.
He murdered Janet. He killed my wife!
I was trying to stop you from doing it!
Yeah, but you did it.
He who smelt it murdered Janet.
Well, it's settled then.
Eleanor and Jianyu are leaving.
For the last time, my name is Jason,
not Jianyu, the amazing
and incredible monk.
Which is why you belong in The Bad Place.
And by the way, Janet is not your wife,
or your soulmate.
-There's a Janet in every neighborhood.
-Well, I'm in love with this Janet.
We did a bunch of amazing, awesome stuff
which almost turned out to be sex,
-and we were married in a legal ceremony.
-It was not legal.
Okay, J-bones, you and me, outside.
What? But...
I'm not going. I don't wanna.
Well, I don't wanna either,
but let's face it.
Chidi and Tahani
are better people than we are.
We tried to improve ourselves
and we did a good job.
Well, I did a good job.
You mostly fell asleep in class
or made fart noises with your hands.
-I could never do that on Earth.
-[fart noises]
This place truly is paradise.
-[Tahani] Look at them.
-[sighs]
Whispering away like
two beefeaters on a tea break.
-I bet they're plotting against us.
-No way. Eleanor wouldn't do that.
You do have feelings for her, don't you?
[stutters] Yes.
But no. Please don't make me think
about this again. My brain will break.
I'm sorry, it's just that I have
certain feelings for you.
I don't mean to contribute to your misery,
it's just that I'm frightened.
I don't have an actual soulmate.
What's gonna happen to me
when Jason and Fake Eleanor go
-and you're off with Real Eleanor?
-[sighs]
Whither Tahani?
Okay, team meeting. [sighs]
Jason has agreed
that the two of us should go.
Bye, Tahani.
Sorry for everything.
After I'm gone, you can go ahead
and clean out my bud hole.
Thank you.
I love you so much, baby.
Promise me you'll visit.
I will not.
It is literally impossible
for me to do that.
Well, it's been real, dawg.
Sorry, that's how I ended
most of my serious relationships.
Yeah. Mmm, that checks out.
I feel like I failed you.
No. Don't ever think that.
I was dropped into a cave,
and you were my flashlight.
[Tahani] Oh!
Goodbye forever.
I will miss you so much.
Ugh. I'll miss you too,
you sexy skyscraper.
All right. [sighs] Ready to go?
Let's grab Michael.
[knock at door]
[Eleanor] Come in.
Hi, guys. Sorry to interrupt.
Um, I'm going to The Bad Place.
I'm taking one of the slots.
-What?
-Awesome.
Eleanor, that's crazy. You belong here.
Why would you go?
Everyone here is supposed
to have a soulmate,
and my soulmate doesn't love me.
I don't know if you love the other Eleanor
or Tahani or someone else,
but you don't love me,
which means that this
will never really be my Good Place.
I'm going, so you only have
to choose one more person.
[door closes]
[stutters] Okay, that means...
What does that mean?
It means...
I get to stay here with my wife forever!
We did it, Eleanor!
USA! USA! USA!
[sighs] This is a real mess, huh?
No matter what they decide,
I'd bet you're gonna be
in pretty hot water with your boss.
Wouldn't be surprised
if retirement were on the table.
Retirement?
Of course, what do I know?
I'm just The All-Knowing Judge
of All Matters in the Afterlife.
But face it, this is your mistake.
-[Val] Morning, Mike.
-Morning, Val.
Oh. Which one's which? I always forget.
Black is regular, orange is anti-matter.
Working on your first solo design, right?
How's it coming?
Do you ever get the feeling
we could be doing it all differently?
I mean, it's always the same.
We get the names,
come up with the design, they arrive,
we move on to the next one.
We never even get to be there
to see how fun it is.
Yeah, I guess,
but don't rock the boat here, pal,
just try to do a good job.
Mmm. French vanilla?
Regular anti-matter's fine. Why flavor it?
A good job.
[Eleanor] All right, nerds,
let's just get this over with.
I'll go to The Bad Place
with Real Eleanor,
-and you three can stay.
-[Jianyu] Yes!
We get to stay, baby! We did it!
Wait, no. You're not going.
I am.
-What?
-Why?
Real Eleanor is my soulmate
or was my soulmate
and she's only going down there
because she thinks that I don't love her.
-Do you?
-I don't know.
Please don't ask me that.
My stomach hurts.
The point is, if she's going
down there because of me,
I'll never be at peace.
-Yes! We get to stay, baby! We did it!
-No, this is bonkers.
-I am going. End of story.
-No, I'm going. End of everything.
What? Now you're trying to replace Chidi?
No. I'm going to replace Real Eleanor.
Chidi and I are going to go together,
which means that you
and Real Eleanor and Jason can stay.
Yes! We get to stay, baby! We did it!
Look, I love you and I think you love me.
We can be together,
away from everyone else.
Obviously, we'll be miserable,
but I truly believe
our love will make us happy.
Okay, you realize The Bad Place is not
some sort of couples retreat, right?
If it is, Janet and I would like to go.
Oh, that's enough out of you, robot lover.
-Hey, that's racist!
-Not a robot.
Oh, you have some nerve.
-Guys?
-[all arguing]
Guys!
[exhales deeply]
[all continue arguing]
Holy motherforking shirtballs.
What?
Wow!
[laughing] Okay, okay.
Whoo!
Yo, Mikey! Shawn! Come on out!
Is everything okay?
Right as rain, Mikey, my boy.
So, Chidi and I are gonna go
to The Bad Place.
-What?
-Trust me, I've got this.
That's our decision. Let's hit it.
Well, what about Real Eleanor?
No, it's me and Chidi. Call the train.
Point of order. I don't accept this offer.
The real mistakes were Jason and Eleanor.
Ga-ga-ga-ga. You said any two of us.
It's me and Chidi. Let's do it to it.
Michael! I just found an obscure precedent
in the rules
that might just save everyone.
Buzz off, Bambadjan! Don't need it.
Oh, okay. [chuckles softly]
Ready when you are, boss.
[Chidi] Eleanor, what's going on?
It took me a while to figure it out,
but just now as we were all
fighting and yelling at each other
and each one of us demanding
we should go to The Bad Place,
I thought to myself,
"Man, this is torture."
And then it hit me.
They're never gonna call a train
to take us to The Bad Place.
The can't, because we're already here.
This is The Bad Place.
[laughs wickedly]
Oh, man!
I can't believe you figured it out.
[laughs wickedly] Oh, God!
You, you ruined everything, you know that?
[Michael laughs] Oh, man.
Eleanor, you really suck!
-[gasps]
-I was so close to pulling it off!
[grunting]
[clatters]
Sorry. So she's right?
Yeah, she figured it out.
[stutters] No,
this doesn't make any sense.
-This is paradise.
-Oh, it looks like paradise,
but it's actually a filthy dumpster
full of our worst anxieties.
I'm surrounded by people
who are literally better than me.
Just me being here forced Chidi
into an ethical "clusterfork."
Tahani tortured Jason
by constantly trying to get him to talk,
Jason tortured me because I was sure
he would blow our cover,
which was torture for Chidi,
because he was responsible for me,
which made Chidi seem
like the perfect soulmate,
and that tortured Tahani
because he didn't love her.
-You don't love me?
-Please, don't ask me that right now.
See?
We've been torturing each other
since the moment we arrived,
and everything Michael has done
has made at least one of us miserable.
-He played us like a fiddle.
-Oh, dip!
Eleanor, I told you that first night
that we were in a prank show.
Oh, yeah.
-You did! Great job, man.
-[Jianyu laughs]
Chidi, don't go!
I don't care if you don't love me,
I love you.
It's the only thing that makes
any sense to me in this crazy world,
-and I think we should stay--
-No, stop, Vicky. They figured it out.
-They...
-They know this is The Bad Place.
Eleanor figured it out.
Ugh, man!
This was supposed to be my big moment.
I just rehearsed that speech
for, like, three hours.
Damn it, Eleanor, you are the worst,
and you can all suck it.
-[door slams]
-Do you remember what I told you
when you predicted you could
do this for 1,000 years?
The time has come to innovate.
The human afterlife can be more fun.
For us, obviously,
not for the people we're torturing.
Who cares about those dummies?
-[laughs wickedly]
-[scattered laughter]
I present to you the perfect recipe
for my proposed experiment.
Four people, perfectly suited
to make each other miserable.
I am going to design an afterlife
where they torture each other.
We've tried this. Humans are very
reticent to torture each other.
Even getting them to do simple things
like pulling out each other's teeth
is like...
I can't think of the right analogy.
Uh, what makes you think
that you can get them to do this?
Because they won't even know
that they are doing it.
I'm going to make them think
that they are in The Good Place,
and to make sure
that they drive each other insane,
I will be there,
posing as a Good Place architect.
-What?
-[murmuring]
I even stole
a Good Place Janet we can use.
-[scoffs]
-[Michael] Look,
we can just send them all to the
hot spike pits with the lava and the bees
and the lightning that tears off
their flesh.
Let's try something new.
I cannot predict everything
that's gonna happen,
but we'll improvise.
We'll be on our toes.
I think that we can get them
to torture each other...
For 1,000 years.
I think you'd be lucky to get six months
out of this insane gambit.
But take me through it.
How would this work, exactly?
Oh. Yes, all right, so... [clears throat]
-This is a 14 million-point plan.
-[footsteps approaching]
Um... Oh. Sorry.
I thought we reserved the conference room.
No, Todd, we have it until 3:00.
Sorry. Sorry, everyone.
So, everyone else in this neighborhood--
Except for you four,
everyone in this neighborhood
is one of us.
After I came up
with everyone's characters,
we'd just create fun scenarios
designed to torture you.
How can I be over it? We haven't
discussed it or even spoken for days.
Well, it sounds like you've had a really
nice vacation from your full-time job.
Get your story straight.
Okay.
They're at each other's throats already.
This should put them over the top.
-Ed, you play Bart, a former private eye.
-Ooh.
I know. Tracy, you're his soulmate,
Nina, a marriage counselor.
[laughing] Maybe we can get them
to swing with us.
[all laughing]
That's perfect, perfect! [shushing]
Hey, guys? It's Michael!
[both groaning]
[Michael] That was really a fun time.
Then it all started to go off the rails.
When I confessed.
You had no idea I was gonna do that,
because honestly,
I had no idea I was gonna do that.
[Michael] Yeah, that came out of nowhere.
I mean, after that, it was just
a crazy scramble for all of us.
You know, I, I definitely underestimated
how effective Chidi was gonna be
teaching you to be good,
and obviously, we didn't anticipate
that Janet would fall in love with Jason.
Hang on. That part is real.
Oh, yeah. Janet isn't one of us.
No, she's sort of a... [sighs]
Foundational mainframe
for all of the neighborhoods,
good and bad.
And apparently,
this Janet is in love with Jason.
I mean... [chuckles] What a world, huh?
[Eleanor] Wait, I don't get something.
I know why Jason and I were
sent here, but why Tahani?
Oh, yeah. Didn't you raise, like,
$1,000 for charity, or whatever?
Uh, 60 billion, actually, so.
Oh.
But it didn't matter...
Because my motivations were corrupt.
I didn't care about helping
the people I raised the money for.
I just wanted to prove my parents wrong,
stick it to my sister,
get fame and attention.
My only real goal
was to snog Ryan Gosling at the Met Ball.
Which I did.
Couple of times, actually.
But wait, why is Chidi here?
Well, uh...
There's something you don't know about me.
I read an article saying
that growing almonds
was bad for the environment,
and yet I continued to use
-almond milk in my coffee--
-No, dingus!
You hurt everyone in your life with
your rigidity and your indecisiveness.
Oh, fork!
You're right.
Every friend, every girlfriend
was driven nuts
because I couldn't do anything.
I missed my mom's back surgery
because I had already promised
my landlord's nephew
that I would help him
figure out his new phone.
I made everyone miserable.
I mean, all this hard work,
all the planning,
all for nothing.
This really sucks.
No, it doesn't.
This is wonderful.
You saw us all on Earth,
a selfish ass, an idiot DJ,
a tortured academic,
a hot, rich fraud with legs for days...
Side note, I might legit be into Tahani.
[chuckles] But that's for another time.
You thought we would torture each other,
and we did for a little,
but we also took care of each other.
We improved each other,
and the four of us became a team.
So, the only thing you succeeded in doing
was bringing us all together.
Oh, Eleanor. That's it!
My big mistake was
bringing you all together,
having you be soulmates
living next to each other.
Next time, I'll spread you out
so it's more of a slow burn.
-Uh, next time?
-[Michael] Yeah.
Yeah, I'm gonna, uh, erase your memories,
you know, make a few changes
and start over again.
Hopefully. Just gotta get
the boss man to sign off.
Wish me luck.
Guys, we need a plan. Quick.
Tahani, anything?
Chidi, I need ya. You're the smart one.
[stammering] I can't. I can't.
-[Eleanor] Jason?
-What? What's up?
Ugh!
What do you say? Take two, huh?
I don't know.
I mean, what is this?
All this work for four people.
Look, for a first attempt
it was actually very promising.
Let me, let me just
tinker a little, try again.
Okay.
But you're way out on a limb here, Mike.
If this thing goes sideways again,
you are done.
Guys, he is going to erase
our memories at any second
and all of this will have been
for nothing.
[grunts] You're useless!
What do I write? What do I write?
Ooh, come on, brain.
Janet?
You can't eat anything, right?
-Correct.
-Open up.
All right, let's try again, shall we?
You know what, bro? Do your worst.
We figured it out once,
we can do it again,
because you know what, Michael?
-Ya bas--
-[snaps fingers]
[water flowing]
Eleanor, come on in.
You, Eleanor Shellstrop, are dead.
Cool.
[Michael] You know the way you feel
when you see
a chimpanzee and a baby tiger
who've become friends?
[laughter]
That's how you're going to feel every day.
[laughter and applause]
[knock at door]
Eleanor? I'm Chris Baker.
I'm your soulmate.
Cool. Bring it in, man.
So where are you from, Chris?
I'm from Teaneck, New Jersey,
and I was a mailman.
Really? [chuckles]
Chris, you'll stand by me
no matter what, right?
Hold that thought.
Is it okay if I go work out?
I love working out. I gotta stay jacked,
it's who I am.
Yeah, you gotta.
Once I'm back,
we'll get to know each other.
Great.
-See ya soon.
-[door closes]
-Hi, there.
-[yelps and gasps]
-Who are you?
-I'm Janet.
I think this is yours.
After I was rebooted,
I found it in my mouth.
What?
What the fork is a "Chidi"?
Why can't I say "fork"?
[inhales]