This is an exciting day.
We are going to tackle
the trolley problem.
Is this a game?
I go first. I call blue.
There's no... No, this is... No.
This is a thought experiment
first introduced by British philosopher
Philippa Foot in 1967.
You are driving a trolley
when the brakes fail.
And on the track ahead of you
are five workmen you will run over.
Now, you can steer to another track,
but on that track
is one person you'd kill
instead of the five.
What do you do?
Do we know anything about the people?
Is one of them an ex-boyfriend
or that snooty girl from Rite Aid
who was always silently judging
my purchases?
It's like, "Yeah, chicky!
A Baby Ruth and birth control,
I see the irony. Keep a-swiping!"
You don't know any of the workers.
That's easy. I switch tracks.
Kill one person instead of five.
This is hard. The only trolley I've been
on is James Franco's ironic trolley.
It travels backwards
from his penguin grotto
to his garage of adult tricycles.
Um... kill one and save five.
Good! But there's many other versions.
What if you knew one of the people?
Does that change the equation?
What if you're not the driver,
you're just a bystander?
Or let's throw the trolley out altogether.
Let's say you're a doctor
and you can save five patients.
But you have to kill one healthy person
and use his organs to do it.
-But that's not the same thing.
-Why not?
It's still choosing to kill one person
to save five, isn't it?
Michael. You've been quiet.
What do you think about this?
Well, obviously the dilemma is clear.
How do you kill all six people?
I would dangle a sharp blade
out the window
to slice the neck of the guy
on the other track
as we smoosh our five main guys.
-I did the thing again, didn't I?
-Yeah. Ten more, buddy.
People. Good. People...
Why is that so hard to remember?
People... What is it?
-Good.
[theme music playing]
Cool. Later, guys.
Oh, hey, twerps.
We have an hour before we have to pretend
to be tortured by Vicky.
Wanna hang out?
We could work on our forced grins.
Check mine out.
[straining] This place
is miserable, et cetera.
-That sounds fun, but...
-Right?
I'm going to dive
into next week's reading. Sorry.
-Jason, do you care to join?
-Sure, dawg.
You're doing extra-credit work?
What can I say?
This class is more fun than I thought.
Eleanor seemed a little suspicious
earlier, snooping around.
You didn't tell her about us, did you?
No.
Why are you scared someone
will know we're pounding it out?
Because you refer to lovemaking
as "pounding it out."
Who cares what people'd
think about us being together?
You should talk about this with a friend.
But that person would know we're together.
Right.
You can talk about why you don't
want anyone to know we're together.
But that person would know
and I don't want anyone to know.
I know.
You should talk to someone
about how weird it is
you don't want to talk to someone
about how we're together.
How's it going, teach?
Hmm. Kitchen looks nice and crazy.
I've been racking my brain
for a way to get through to Michael.
What do you think about writing
a Kierkegaard rap musical?
-I think that's a terrible idea.
-Cool.
Michael won't learn
how to be a good person overnight.
He's not even a person.
He's a bunch of evil
shoved up the butt of an evil mannequin.
Teaching him to be good,
it's like teaching me how to be not hot.
How would you even do it?
You'd have me hunch or something
and then stand there and say,
"Gurp. Gurp. Gurp."
I don't know.
I can't picture it.
I've been hot my whole life.
Sorry, who is this conversation for again?
It's for you.
I believe in you, nerd boy.
If you can teach me and Jason ethics,
you can teach anybody.
Thanks.
But definitely a "no" on the rap musical?
If you really think--
♪ My name is Kierkegaard
And my writing is impeccable ♪
♪ Check out my teleological suspension
Of the ethical ♪
-No.
-No, right?
[chuckles] It felt like a "no"
when I was doing it.
-Janet?
-Hi, there.
If I were to tell you
something personal about myself,
-you couldn't tell anyone, right?
-Right.
In a way, you're like a therapist?
Absolutely not. A therapist is
a trained medical professional
with the ability to absorb and process
complex ideas about human emotion.
I am a vessel containing
all of the knowledge in the universe.
Close enough.
Jason and I are sleeping together.
-Okay.
-No one can ever know.
I wouldn't shag Jason
if he were the last man on Earth.
But, well, he sort of is.
And I am. Shagging him, I mean.
I'm losing my mind.
Please help me.
My job is to make your experience
here in the afterlife more enjoyable.
I will try to help you.
I am going to need some time
to read every book ever written
about human psychotherapy.
I've done that, so let's begin.
Have a seat.
Hi. I'm your therapist, Janet.
[Chidi] I want to chat
about your progress.
In the last homework assignment,
I asked you to examine the ethics
of Les Misérables
in which a man steals a loaf of bread
to feed his starving family.
Would you please read
your first paragraph?
"Everyone in this story sucks
and belongs in the Bad Place.
The thief is bad, the officer chasing him
is bad, all the whiny prostitutes are bad,
plus they're all French, so they're
going to the Bad Place automatically."
Do you see how you're already off-topic?
Chidi, I've been around a long time.
Like, all of it.
I know for a fact
if you steal a loaf of bread,
it's a negative 17 points.
Twenty if it's a baguette,
because that makes you more French.
Okay, sure,
but philosophy is about questioning things
you take for granted
and I don't think you're doing that.
I mean, "I personally know
Victor Hugo is in the Bad Place,
being tortured.
He's a real wuss, too.
If a lava monster
even gets near the guy, he's like,
'Sacrebleu, I peed in m' pants.'"
I don't know what you want from me.
That's exactly what he said.
Jason's a nice person, but my suitors
were always of a certain echelon.
I used what I call the duke rule,
because "duke" is both minimum-acceptable
university and rank of nobility.
You've never dated anyone
like Jason before.
I've dallied below my station.
I had a fling
with a non-famous Hemsworth brother.
But even Larry Hemsworth
had more status than Jason.
Jason didn't even have a job.
In a sad way, not in the good, rich way.
Hi, guys. What are you doing?
Sitting in a room? That's pretty cool.
I took your suggestion. I'm talking
to Janet about our relationship.
Actually, it might help
if I could hear Jason's side as well.
No, that'll only slow things down.
I'll tell you his side.
He thinks I have to control everything
and he has no voice in this relationship.
Right, Jason? Good.
Now, where were we?
Just heard that.
Okay, fine. I'll leave.
[Chidi] I just don't feel like
you're engaging with the material.
Like with the trolley problem.
That was just tricky, that's all.
Why don't you tell me the right answer?
That's what's so great
about the trolley problem,
is that there is no right answer.
[groans]
This is why everyone hates
moral philosophy professors.
I'm on your side, dude,
but he is not wrong.
Okay. Michael, trust me.
When it comes to human ethics,
I just know more than you.
I've been studying it my whole life.
It's just that it's so theoretical.
I mean, you know,
maybe there's a more concrete approach.
Here. Let's try this.
Oh, God! Michael, what did you do?
I made the trolley problem real
so we could see how the ethics
would actually play out.
There are five workers on this track
and one there.
Here are the levers to switch the tracks.
Make a choice!
The thing is... Ethically speaking--
No time, dude! Make a decision!
Well, it's tricky!
On the one hand, if you ascribe
to a purely utilitarian worldview--
[brakes squealing]
Okay. So...
what did we learn?
Chidi?
Talk it out, buddy.
What are we thinking?
He thinks he just killed
a bunch of people with a trolley.
It's just a simulation.
I'd never make you kill real people.
Well, that's reassuring.
Because some of the parts
of the fake people flew into my mouth!
Michael, can we just go
back to the classroom?
We never left. I'll show you.
[sighs]
Yeah.
Okay.
See, buddy? None of this was real.
Well, they're fake people,
but their pain is real.
Does that make sense?
There have to be stakes
or it's just a thought experiment.
This is awful.
You specifically asked me
if there was a way
I could connect with the material more.
I'm trying, you guys.
Sorry. You're right.
I want to help you understand this.
Thank you, Chidi.
So, let's try again.
[wheels clanking]
[stammers] I thought maybe
we would have a discussion.
No, the whole point
is to play out the scenario in real time.
Quick, Chidi! What's your decision?
Okay, I can do this.
I am choosing to switch tracks,
so that way I only kill one person.
[Michael] Forgot to tell you,
this is the scenario
where you know one of the people.
It's your friend Henry there.
-Chidi! How are you, mate?
-Henry! Move!
Ah! Nice trolley.
-[Chidi] Move out of the way!
-I can't, Chidi.
-My boots are stuck in the tracks.
-Henry, move!
-Anyway, long time, no--
-Move out of there!
Wait! [screams]
Oh, my God!
[brakes squealing]
Again, just a simulation.
An almost impossibly lifelike simulation.
Would someone's foot
really fly off their body like that?
That was kind of cool.
Ethically speaking.
Tahani's confusing.
She's really smart.
She's all soft and smooth
like a bunch of water balloons.
But I tell her she's pretty
a hundred times a day
and she's never said I'm pretty once.
And how does that make you feel?
I feel Tahani's embarrassed
I'm not some scientist
who forecloses on banks.
-I need another session with Janet.
-[Jason] It's my turn.
I have a lot of problems, too.
Perhaps we could kill two birds
with one Janet, as it were.
How would you feel about giving
Jason and me couples therapy?
I'd feel great.
Janet? What's happening?
Unclear.
My guess is I'm operating in a way
I'm not designed for
and it's creating a small glitch.
But if I'm helping you guys, I say,
"What has one thumb
and wants to keep going?
This not-lady."
Eh? Eh?
Okay, so that was trolley problem
version number seven.
Chidi opted to run over
five William Shakespeares
instead of one Santa Claus.
As much as I'm enjoying
watching random people's heads fly off,
I think we've taken this trolley thing
as far as it can go.
-You might be right, Eleanor.
-Thank you.
Let's try the doctor one.
Dude! What the fork?
[Michael] These five people all need
organ transplants or they will die.
Eleanor's perfectly healthy.
Chidi, do you want to slice her open
and use her organs
to save the five sick people?
Chidi, think about this.
I'm your hottest friend. No, Tahani.
I'm your nicest... No, Jason.
I'm your friend!
[Chidi] I won't do it.
As a doctor, I've taken
the Hippocratic oath to do no harm.
Although five people will die,
I cannot harm one innocent person
to save them and forsake my oath.
It's unethical.
-Okay, tell their families.
-What?
[girl] Doctor Chidi?
My daddy needed a heart transplant.
Did you save his life?
He was working,
then a really bad man
ran him over with a trolley.
Oh! Come on!
What? I'm finding this incredibly helpful.
I'm really starting to get it.
I know!
We'll do the one where you're in a boat
next to a volcano
and you can either save 50 people
or one awesome dog or whatever.
No, no, no.
Hey! Are you torturing us again?
What?
You don't care
about learning ethics lessons.
You're just torturing Chidi again,
aren't you?
-Busted.
-What?
[laughs maniacally]
I'm sorry.
Old habits die hard.
Not as hard as those people
you crushed with the trolley, though.
-Boom!
-I'm sorry, is this funny to you?
Yeah. I thought that was clear
from my laughter.
Oh, come on.
My bad.
I'm still on your team, okay?
I just needed to let off
a little steam. [grunts]
See? Back home, all good.
No. No, not all good.
You keep saying we need you
or we'll end up getting tortured forever.
But then, when we do help you out,
we still end up getting tortured.
I'd rather just be tortured
than choose it.
You are no longer welcome in my class.
Get the fork out!
But I said, "My bad."
Out!
[Eleanor] You okay?
You've been staring at the second page
of this book for an hour.
When I'm really upset,
concentrating on a table of contents
helps me calm down.
It's like a menu, but the food is words.
Oh. Okay.
I can't believe I actually thought
he wanted to learn from us.
What he really wanted was to torture me.
Using the thing I love most in the world.
Woven belts?
Oh! Teaching, right.
I'm sorry about this, Chidi.
I made him take the classes
and I feel a little responsible.
No, no, it's not your fault.
Yeah, you're right, it isn't,
and no takebacks.
No, a tiger can't change his stripes.
This is what he always wanted.
Me trying desperately to teach him
something he never intended to learn
so I'd end up miserable
with my glasses all smudged up
from sweaty forehead stress grease.
Okay. Gross.
Also, I really don't think that's true.
No? What possible other reason
could he have to behave that way?
Actually, I can think of one.
Yesterday, Tahani gave us her reasons
not to take this relationship public.
-Tahani, what do you value about Jason?
-Well, he's thoughtful.
Picks flowers and brings them to me.
Often, they're ones
I've just planted, but...
That's how I know they're fresh.
He's the least self-aware person
I've ever met.
He has massive amounts
of unearned confidence
and he's utterly unaware
of his own absurdity.
Therefore, quite good at sex.
Here's the thing.
I'm nice to you and you're mean to me.
There's something wrong about that,
but I can't put my finger on what it is.
Jason, I genuinely like you
but it's hard to change all at once.
Can you give me a little more time?
Okay.
I agree to keep this on the DL for now
if you agree to grab my butt in public
once a week.
You can say I sat in gum
and you're trying to scrape it off.
You do sit in a lot of gum.
[Janet] Aw. I'm happy for you guys.
[retches]
[ribbits]
-[ribbits]
-Huh.
Look, I don't know what to tell you.
If Chidi can't take a joke, that's on him.
Just like all that blood was.
[chuckles]
I can't high-five that!
No matter how badly I want to.
Look, this isn't about Chidi
not being able to take a joke.
This is about you.
You're doing what I used to do.
You're pulling an Eleanor.
Posting my cousin's credit card number
on Reddit because she said I looked tired?
[both chuckle]
I forgot I did that.
No. No.
Pulling an Eleanor in this case is
lashing out when you feel like a failure.
You couldn't hack the classes.
They made you feel dumb and small,
so you took it out on the teacher.
You think I feel dumb and small?
I'm an eternal being
who can see in nine dimensions.
I can see from your aura
you're about to fart quietly
then lie about it.
And please don't,
because I can also see what you ate today.
Dude, you can bluster
and insult all you want.
Also classic Shellstrop moves, by the way.
But deep down, you know I'm right.
Whatever.
Eventually Chidi will get over it.
[chuckles] Leaving it up to
the other person to be the grown-up.
Yet another classic Shellstrop move.
You and I are really very similar.
What does that say about me?
Look, bro, it's 100% on you
to make this up to him.
[Michael] I screwed up.
I'm owning it.
I mean, I'm a superior being.
I ought to act like one. Right?
So, I really thought
about each one of you,
and I got you something
that will make you happy.
I call them "opposite tortures."
-Do you mean "presents"?
-That's better. Thank you.
Tahani, here's yours.
Holy mama!
Is this a diamond?
Yeah. Honestly, I don't get the appeal.
Diamonds are literally carbon molecules
lined up in the most boring way.
They're worthless space garbage.
What you're holding right now,
that's basically meteorite poop.
And I have the biggest piece!
Eleanor, I had Janet make you
a never-ending shrimp dispensary.
[Eleanor gasps]
[Michael laughs]
[exclaims loudly]
This is the dream.
-It is?
-Yeah.
Jason, here you go.
[gasps] Pikachu! Guys, it's Pikachu!
This is awesome.
Aw, man.
And, finally, Chidi.
You were a tough nut to crack,
but I think I figured it out.
This is a replica of a lost notebook
from the desk of Immanuel Kant.
It contains never-before-seen thoughts
and musings and several...
crude, erotic doodles.
Interesting guy, actually.
The point is no one on Earth
has ever seen this, except for you.
Cool.
This isn't an apology.
It's a bribe and I'm not interested.
Yeah, we can't be bought!
What do you want from me, man?
You want me to give you
a golden nameplate for your office?
Or you want a diamond
bigger than Tahani's?
No! Then this would be worthless.
I don't want anything.
Oh... Okay. I get it.
I get it.
You want me to admit I was wrong.
You want me to say, "Chidi, I'm so sorry,
because I didn't understand human ethics
and you do.
It made me feel insecure and I lashed out.
And please help me, because I feel
so, so lost and vulnerable."
Yes.
Oh, Chidi, I'm so sorry.
I didn't understand human ethics
and you do.
And it made me feel insecure
and I lashed out.
And I really need your help,
because I feel so lost and vulnerable.
Have a seat.
[sniffles]
Whoo!
Nobody try "mystery flavor."
It's white chocolate and it is nasty.
Listen, we just wanted to thank you
for all of your help.
Our relationship's grown so much stronger
over the past few weeks
and we owe it all to you.
Congratulations.
I am very happy for the both of you.
[rumbling and crashing]
Okay, bye!
Hi, there.
What's happening? What's wrong?
I am wrong. I can't stop glitching.
I don't know why and it's getting worse.
I fear this neighborhood
is in danger of total collapse.
So that's the main thing. How are you?