Go back to the void, babe.
I'll be there in a minute.
Okay. I'll miss you like crazy.
-I'll miss you more.
-No! I'll miss you more.
-Bye!
-[chuckles]
It's my first time making someone.
He might be a little bit off.
Janet, you can't just go around
inventing people.
-Get rid of him immediately.
-No. Eleanor said to find a rebound guy.
I couldn't find one, so I made one.
-He's helping me forget about Jason.
-[groans]
Jason. Jason. Jason. Jason. Jason.
Jason. Jason. Jason. Jason.
-Jason. Jason. Jason. Jason. [exclaims]
-Honey.
-Babe...
-Jason. Jason. Jason.
-Babe!
-Ja--
-Don't be jealous.
-[exclaims]
I love you now.
We'll spend every second together.
No, no! No, you are not.
Janet, no one can know about...
-I'm sorry, what's your name again?
-Derek Hostetler.
If anybody finds out about him,
we are doomed.
He has to stay in your void.
It's our void now.
[laughs] We moved in together!
What? Can you believe it?
-I got a hanger for my jumpsuit.
-What do you--
I mean, that's so fast!
When you know, you know.
And we know literally everything.
We are so in sync,
we're finishing each other's--
Derek!
[theme music playing]
-Hey, guys.
-[gasps]
Michael, you frightened me.
Jason's making me watch this horror film
about two ex-convicts who try to rob
and murder a neglected child.
Get over here!
Hey! I got some great news.
I've arranged for you
to have a weekend getaway.
I bet you're tired
of being cooped up here.
I am a bit.
All this time indoors has degraded my skin
from radiant to merely dewy.
Me? Dewy?
There's going to be plenty
of sun and fun
at the private campsite I set up
for you at the edge of the neighborhood.
Here you go.
I told Vicky I'll be torturing you
for the time being.
Relax, live it up.
Out you go. Here.
Now, sadly, Janet is still offline
so you can't call her, okay?
The best news is,
none of this is suspicious.
I don't know what's gonna happen to us,
but I need to tell you something...
-I love you.
-What are you watching?
Um, Cannonball Run II.
Again?
You watch that movie a lot.
Well, it's basically my favorite movie
of all time.
You can't watch it.
This copy's mine.
Uh-oh. I guess I'm still pretty selfish.
Help! I need another ethics lesson, quick!
Weird energy coming from you
right now.
Hey, guys. What you doing?
Nothing? Great.
So, Chidi, just want to double-check,
how do ethical philosophers feel
about murder?
It's frowned upon.
Okay, what if the reason
you want to murder someone
is to make your life easier?
That's okay, right?
-Is there a problem here, bud?
-Okay, I'll just tell you. Uh...
No, too hard to explain.
I'll show you. Janet.
-Hi, there.
-Hey, there.
-Who the fork is that?
-Derek Hostetler, PI.
Derek is my rebound guy.
I made him.
Oh.
Did you do that because of what I said?
-Yes. Because of what you said.
-Janet--
-Thank you.
You know, you seem so sad.
Do you want me
to make you a boyfriend?
-I could have a brother?
-Yes!
Based on your last 10,000 comments,
it would be
"Stone Cold" Steve Austin's head
-on Tahani's body.
-Or vice versa.
She's not gonna make you anything.
Janet, that'll be all.
Okay. Goodbye. Say goodbye, Derek.
Goodbob. I hope we same place again
very now.
[Janet laughs]
-His brain is wrong.
-[laughs]
-Mmm.
The goal is to tap the ball hard enough
to go through the wicket,
but not so hard it goes too far through.
It combines both classic aspects
of British sport, whimsy and restraint.
Oh! So restrained.
I believe it was
Prime Minister Neville Chamberlain
who called croquet "barely a game."
It's kind of fun, I guess.
But can I teach you a different game?
You whack it as hard as you can,
in whatever direction you want.
Jaguars rule!
The Jaguars are very good!
-Ooh!
-Whoa! Nice!
Mmm.
[laughing]
-Thor!
-Well done!
Okay. Here's where I am on this.
We gotta kill Derek.
No, think about it.
What if Vicky calls for Janet
and Derek shows up too?
She'll have questions we can't answer.
But Derek does seem to be helping Janet
get over Jason.
Right?
No earthquakes since he showed up.
But if we get rid of Derek,
maybe Janet will start glitching again.
If we can't kill Derek,
we gotta break up Jason and Tahani.
If that relationship ends,
then Janet won't feel sad anymore
and maybe she'll get rid of Derek herself.
Girl, you are a messy bench
who loves drama and I am into it.
I'm sorry, Michael,
but that's also ethically dicey.
Here comes the egghead.
Jason and Tahani are happy together.
Telling them he was once married
to Janet might cause them harm.
It's not permissible
to ruin their happiness to save ourselves.
But isn't keeping a secret
from someone basically like lying, though?
No, it's okay to keep a secret,
as long as it isn't harming anyone
and telling them that secret
might cause harm.
Noice!
Cool. Good point, egghead.
I'll tell you what else
would cause them harm,
getting caught
and sent to the real Bad Place
to be tortured for eternity,
which will happen
if Derek blows our cover.
I know! But we'll also be sent
to the real Bad Place
if we do bad things.
I know it's tempting to take a shortcut,
but moral strength is defined
by how we behave in times of stress.
Has anyone ever told you
what a drag you are?
Everyone. Constantly.
[Tahani mimics fanfare]
I hereby pronounce you King Jason.
Dope.
Where did you learn how to do this?
The Hertfordshire Academy
for Expressionless Girls,
a finishing school I attended
before Oxford,
and then of course the Sorbonne.
I haven't asked
where you were educated.
I went to Lynyrd Skynyrd High School
in northeast Jacksonville,
which was really just a bunch of tugboats
tied together.
Didn't you get seasick?
No, sorry, they were tied together
in a junkyard.
It wasn't a very good school.
For most of my classes, we sold
dirty magazines door-to-door.
You know, Jason, every single detail
about your life is deeply disturbing.
And yet, I envy you.
I was never allowed to goof off.
I never had a friend
I could be myself around.
Maybe I can be that friend.
Or your husband!
-Okay, stop it.
-No, no, no, I'm serious.
Will you marry me?
[Eleanor]
I say we just let sleeping dogs lie.
Tell Janet Derek can stay,
but she's gotta keep him under wraps,
so no other demons don't find out.
Fine. As long as they fly under the radar
and Janet stays happy,
I think we'll be safe. Janet?
-You always do this!
-You don't respect me
and you never have!
You make a federal case out of everything!
Because to you, I'll always be
that guy you made!
Guys! What's going on?
Can we not do this in front of my friends?
So they're your friends now.
I'm stating a fact.
They are your friends.
I don't know these people.
I am out of here.
-Oh, great, Derek.
-I'm gonna go back to our void
and I'm gonna try and forget
this ever happened.
-It is not your void. It is my void!
-Oh. Wow.
I know it's
a boundless, barren nothingness,
but you are always there.
-Fine, I'll go somewhere else.
-Fine!
No, not fine! Don't go somewhere else!
Okay. Yeah.
We're forked, aren't we?
Look, Jason, you're lovely
and I've had a wonderful time
these past few weeks,
but why on Earth would I marry you?
Well, for one thing, we're not on Earth.
Decent point.
Also, we like each other.
And I promise to always be nice to you.
Okay.
I'll marry you. But I need some time
to plan a proper reception.
Where will everyone sit?
Michael and Janet
opposite Chidi and Eleanor
or Michael and Eleanor opposite
Janet and Chidi?
Let's have it today. At the beach!
The beach is where
all the best stuff happens,
like swimsuit issues
and Saving Private Ryan,
-and Jersey Shore and crabs!
-Okay.
Oh, I hope Janet's back online.
-Janet?
-Hi, there.
-Is everything all right?
-Yeah.
Mmm-hmm. Everything's fine. It's okay.
I'm fine.
So it's all fine. [laughs]
How can I help you?
-Wait. There he is!
-[gasps]
Derek. How are you? Nice to meet you.
-Derek, get down!
-Come here!
I am not coming down
because I'm meant to come here.
I came here on purpose
'cause this tree is my new house.
This is Derek's house
and Janet's not allowed in,
because I booby-trapped it.
Hi.
Janet! You're here! Thank God!
Derek, I am not talking to you right now.
I'm here to announce that Jason Mendoza
and Tahani Al-Jamil
are getting married this evening.
"The ceremony will be private,
but we think it would be totally dope
if you biznatches came
and got turnt up with us afterward."
I can guess who wrote the invitation.
How come you never get this upset
at anything I do, Janet?
Do not start with me right now, Derek!
I will start it.
-No, no, no, don't!
-Okay.
-Do not avoid me by going to the void!
-No, no, no!
-What a little bench!
-[Chidi groans]
Things are falling apart here.
Chidi, I understand the ethics involved,
but we need to stop that wedding!
We break up Jason and Tahani.
Janet stops being sad. Derek goes away.
Fine, but...
[both groan]
There's something called
the doctrine of double effect.
To remain ethical, you can't go into this
with the intention of killing Derek.
Your only goal has to be to spare
Jason and Tahani from future pain
by filling them in on Jason's past.
No, I got you.
So, ethically we should tell Jason
he used to be married to Janet
and it would be terrible
if that ultimately led to Derek's death.
-Wink.
-No. Winking is bad.
You should not be winking
or saying the word "wink."
Okay. We really need to kill...
We really need to kill any suspicion
that I wanna murder Derek.
Boom!
Wink.
Tahani, you're so smart.
Every day you teach me something new
about art and history,
and why I shouldn't eat
everything that smells good
because sometimes it's candles.
You're basically
like a hot, genius teacher
who sometimes has sex with me,
your student.
That used to happen a lot
at Lynyrd Skynyrd High School,
but this time you won't be arrested.
Oh. I love you, Tahani.
Braap, braap, braap, braap!
Pew! Pew!
Jason, I never guessed
we'd be where we are today.
Me, a prominent British philanthropist
with award-winning legs,
set to marry you, a swamp dweller
who once asked me
if the presidents on Mount Rushmore
have butts on the other side.
We don't make any sense together,
yet, when I'm with you,
I can really let my hair down.
Metaphorically speaking,
since I'd never have it up
in the first place. [chuckling]
I'm not a factory worker.
But you've helped me to see that there is
more to life than just appearances.
And I can't believe I'm about to say this,
but I think I love--
[Michael] Wait! Stop the ceremony!
This wedding cannot happen.
[Eleanor] This is not helpful,
but I have always wanted to be a part of
a wedding that was stopped dramatically.
[Jason] We can't get married?
-Why not?
-[Michael] Because...
Because... Hang on a second.
I can't do it.
Professor Buzzkill got in my head.
I'm thinking about all the rules
I have to follow to stay ethical.
Someone else has to do this.
I... No.
All right.
I hate to be the bearer of bad news--
Uh, I think you mean "bad news bear."
Before all the reboots,
Jason was married to Janet.
Okay? That's why Janet's been glitching.
Because she's sad. She misses Jason.
In fact, she was so sad that she...
Well... Derek?
Well, well, well.
Jason Mendoza.
At last we meet.
You've got a lot of nerve, buddy.
-No, no, I'm Eleanor, man.
-What?
Everybody, this is Derek.
Janet made Derek as a boyfriend
to try and rebound from Jason.
Oh, I feel quite light-headed.
Janet, fetch my tizzy couch, please.
[sighs]
Decision time.
Any second,
someone'll realize we're all missing.
Why don't you reboot all of us?
Tahani and Jason
will forget they were ever in love.
It was a fluky thing,
it probably won't happen again,
and Chidi and I can forget
anything we want to forget.
You know, like personal bloopers
that were embarrassing
or days where we
were very gassy, et cetera.
We'll meet back in your office,
you bring us up to speed
and we go from there.
No, no, no, we're not starting over.
We've come too far.
Our only options are to reboot
either Janet or Derek.
Neither one is permissible
as your primary intention.
The doctrine of double effect, remember?
Well, man, I'm working with the doctrine
of not being completely effed. Okay?
I don't understand
what you even like about Jason.
What does he have that I don't?
A soul. And genitals.
Here we go
with this whole no-genitals thing again.
You gave me wind chimes
instead of a penis.
This isn't about your wind chime penis.
It's not about you at all.
I don't even know what it is about,
which is very confusing,
because the whole point of me
is that I know everything!
Janet, can I speak to you alone
for a second?
Okay, look, when you said
you were sad about Jason
and I suggested,
"Hey, find a rebound guy,"
it's 'cause I thought it was
some schoolgirl crush,
like some guy you made out with
a couple of times
in the walk-in freezer
of a Bruegger's Bagels.
Not based on a real example.
Yes, it is.
His name was Marcus Bicksburger.
"Marcus"? I always called him Ben.
-Look, I gave you bad advice. Okay?
-Uh-huh.
-Jason was clearly important to you.
-Yeah.
And real heartbreak
doesn't have a simple cure.
You will feel better
after some time goes by.
I don't really experience
the passing of time.
I do use it as a lotion occasionally.
Weird, but keep doing it
'cause your skin looks amazing.
Thank you. Not skin.
The point is,
to get through a real heartbreak,
you have to sit with your feelings
and mull it over and power through.
And you have to talk about it.
[groans]
Talking about your feelings is the worst.
It's so much easier to find a rebound guy
and have sex about your feelings.
I don't know if I wanna
talk to Jason right now.
That's cool.
Until then, if you ever need a friend
to talk to, just know I'm here.
Derek.
There's no easy way to say this.
I never should have made you.
-It's time for you to go away.
-I understand, because you understand.
Janet, this relationship has been
the best seven hours of my whole life.
It's been the only seven hours
of my whole life.
I made you this morning.
We all remember.
-Okay, you ready to do this?
-Yep.
Janet.
What are you doing?
I imbued Derek
with some of my thoughts and emotions.
This is the only way I can reabsorb them.
It'll just be a minute.
Dang it.
That is some hot reabsorbing.
Can you get pregnant from reabsorbing?
Uh-oh. I hear wind chimes.
Everybody, look away.
I'll keep watching,
but you guys look away.
[chuckles]
Goodbye, Derek.
Goodbye, mommy-girlfriend.
Bye, everybody. Derek's going away now.
Does he seem a little bit still alive?
He's about as dead as he can be.
Like he's in power saver mode.
[Derek] Derek.
Are you worried
you might start glitching again?
No. I'll be okay now that I understand
what I'm going through
and now I know I can talk
to my friends about it.
I'm gonna toss this steamer trunk
containing the lifeless husk
of my ex-boyfriend
into a remote corner of my limitless void.
-Bye, guys.
-[Derek] Derek!
[Eleanor sighs]
[Jason] I'm kinda glad
we didn't get married today.
Me too.
Perhaps we were rushing things a bit.
We don't know
that much about each other.
Like, who was the first person you kissed?
The sexy mouse robot
in the Chuck E. Cheese band.
-Yeah, it was--
-Okay.
Okay. That's probably enough
get-to-know-each-other for now.
We'll take things slow.
I know I'm technically married to Janet,
but I don't remember it at all.
I'm sorry that it puts you
in a weird position.
And I still like you a lot.
Me too.
What happens now?
Don't know.
Do you wanna try reabsorbing me?
[laughs]
-Something wrong?
-No.
Yep.
I've been keeping a secret from you
about you.
What is it?
The thing is it's not even harming you
and if I tell you,
I feel like might harm you.
So, ethically speaking,
I don't think I have to tell you.
Well, forget all that.
This is freaking me out,
I'm losing my mind, so tell me.
And you don't need to respond,
'cause I know you have trouble
saying how you feel.
I love you, too.
I've never been that certain
about anything.
I once even tried to rent socks.
How did I say that that easily?
I get how you said it.
I'm a total smoke-show.
But how did I say it so easily?
I don't wanna talk about this,
but after everything
that's happened today, we gotta.
So, let's just get it all out there.
Um...
Yeah, I guess, do you...
I don't know. Do you have feelings
like that for me again now?
I'm sorry, but I don't think I do.
"Sorry"? Why are you sorry?
'Cause I'm relieved,
because I don't either.
So, all good.
-I mean, I feel incredibly close to you--
-No, no!
-In many--
-You don't need to explain yourself.
We are on the same page. Okay? Good.
[Michael] Hey, guys.
Sorry, I know it's late.
Can I talk to Eleanor for a second?
We're chatting about something right now.
It's cool, we were wrapping up.
Good talk, bro.
[Eleanor] What's on your mind?
Well, being ethical, it's hard.
And I kind of hate it.
When's it get easier?
Why don't you ask Chidi?
He's the ethics master.
I'm a newbie and I still suck at it.
Yeah. That's why I'm asking you.
I designed this entire torture chamber
around the absolute certainty
that when the going got tough,
you would give up.
That was the signature Shellstrop move.
Do you remember once
when your "change oil" light came on?
You abandoned your car
in a parking garage.
Of course.
But here, faced with the toughest
challenges I could throw at you,
you never once stopped trying
to become a better person
and I just... Why?
I don't know.
Whenever I would do something
crappy on Earth,
there would be a tiny voice
in the back of my head
that would say, "Eleanor, don't grab that
handful of olives from the salad bar.
You didn't pay for that."
Or, "Eleanor,
don't spit those olive pits
onto the floor of the grocery store.
That's not cool."
Or, "Eleanor, that old man
slipped on your olive pit
and he fell down.
Don't use the fact everyone's distracted
to steal more olives."
-I get it.
-This ethics stuff, it's hard
and it's confusing.
It is such a buzzkill.
But it does get rid of the little voice,
because at least I'm trying
to do the right thing
instead of the crappy thing.
And I gotta say, man,
I don't miss the little voice.
Well, thank you for helping me today.
Wow! You, uh... you really did
just come here to chat, didn't you?
Just shoot the shirt
with your old pal, Eleanor.
-I guess so, yeah. Why?
-It's just a very human-y thing to do.
Stick with the program, demon buddy.
I feel like things are starting
to click in our little study group.
Hello, Michael.
Shut the door. Have a seat.