Hello, Michael. Shut the door.
Have a seat.
When you proposed
this new form of torture,
we all laughed behind your back.
Some people called you names,
like the Thomas Edison of incompetence
or "that dick."
[chuckles]
But it seems you've pulled it off.
-What you've done here is amazing.
-Really?
Yes. These reports are remarkable.
Your humans
are experiencing emotional torture
at the same level of physical torture
created by our squiggliest
eyeball corkscrews.
I'm jubilant.
As a result of our success,
I'm getting a seat on the High Council.
We will expand our neighborhood idea
and you will oversee the project.
You are being promoted.
Your senior staff pin.
Congratulations.
This is everything you've ever wanted.
This is everything I've ever wanted.
Oh! [chuckles]
This is everything I've ever wanted!
Oh, wow!
You're really happy?
Can't you tell?
I'm basically squealing
like a birthday girl.
[theme music playing]
At some point,
we should discuss yesterday's events.
Do you mean us almost getting married
and then finding out
I was married to Janet?
Then Janet making a boyfriend to forget me
and then Janet
getting rid of that boyfriend?
Or do you mean
when we saw that cool cloud?
The first bit.
Perhaps after Michael briefs us
on how we're going to be
fake-tortured today,
we can sit down and chat?
Yes. Good idea.
-Yo, Chidi?
-Yeah?
Wanna hear about a cool cloud I saw?
Come in.
I'd like to start by saying something
I wanted to say for a very long time.
Surprise, idiots!
You're all in the Bad Place.
[Michael and Shawn laughing]
That's right, nerds.
Everything around you, all you can see,
is an elaborate system of torture
designed just for you.
Sorry, we're in the Bad Place?
Why are you revealing this now?
It was an experiment and it worked.
So, my boss is promoting me.
Sorry, I should've introduced you.
This is my boss, Shawn.
Hello, imbeciles.
We need to study
everything that happened here.
There was a first version that collapsed,
but the second has been a huge success.
We'll shut this place down.
The four of you will be brought
to the real Bad Place,
where your brains
will be removed, studied,
then batted about a stadium
like beach balls.
Your arms will be peeled like bananas.
That part's just for fun.
[chuckles] Right.
And then you will be, you know,
tortured forever.
Michael, is this all true?
Yes, Eleanor, it is.
You're such a rube,
thinking you could become a better person.
You got Chidi
to teach you stupid philosophy?
Like those old farts
were gonna provide guidance.
"Oh, Kierkegaard is so great.
Have you read Fear and Trembling?"
Well, I don't know.
Have you read Boring and Stupid?
Because that's what you are.
-Nice.
-Thank you.
How long will it take you
to shut down the neighborhood?
[Michael] Better part of a day.
In the meantime, why don't we have
a farewell party tonight?
To thank the crew for all the hard work?
We could jam to some tunes.
Destroy the place,
play beer pong with Jason's testicles.
What do you say, boss?
Sure. By the way,
I know what you're thinking.
-"Maybe Janet can help."
-Ah.
You're wrong. Janet?
[gasps] Oh, hi, little cuties.
[chuckles] I love you guys so much.
Except for you, Jason, because I hate you.
[chuckles] I hate you.
Janet? What's wrong?
Oh, where's my phone?
We put a Restraining Bracelet on her,
disrupting her powers.
It's made of mag-a-nets.
Mag-nets. Mag-a-nittens...
Magnets are supposed to
make me feel drunk.
But guess what? I feel fine.
[chuckling]
I can't believe Michael betrayed us again.
Why is it always the ones you most expect?
I should've seen this coming.
No one can truly turn over a new leaf.
Ben Affleck told me he'd matured
after he directed Argo.
But then, right on schedule, it was,
"Guess what, Tahani? I'm gonna be Batman!"
There's only one option.
Shawn clearly doesn't know
Michael has rebooted this neighborhood
800 times.
I say we trade that information
for some kind of reduced sentence.
[Tahani] Chidi, they're monsters.
Who's to say they won't agree to a deal
and then turn around and install us
into their horrible human zoo?
[Chidi] There's no other option.
There's no way for a human
to get that bracelet off Janet.
If there were, we could get her to call us
a train to Mindy St. Claire's house.
We know for a fact
the people from the Bad Place
can't follow us there and I vote for that.
I vote we...
No, sorry. And no offense, Jason,
but the stakes here are too high
to let someone with your limited
intellectual processing capacity weigh in.
I was gonna agree with you.
Oh, great. That's two votes for my plan.
All right. Eleanor, what do you think?
Trade information on Michael
or try to escape to the Medium Place?
Neither. I vote we ignore
everything Michael just said
and assume he's still on our side.
Who's with me?
Sorry, but when all this started,
you said Michael wasn't trustworthy.
Now you want us to trust him?
Yes. For one very specific
and rock-solid reason.
What's-his-name.
Who?
The dude!
The super depressing religious guy,
the real buzzkill
whose name I can never remember.
Keeblers... Car. Kyra. Sedgwick?
Oh, I love her. Dear friend of mine.
Not important right now.
Kierkegaard?
Yes! Kierkegaard!
When Michael was mocking us,
whose name did he use? Kierkegaard.
He was sending us a message.
To take a leap of faith.
'Cause that was Kierkegaard's thing,
right?
Yes, but it's probably
better translated as
"a leap into faith."
-It's so hard to be your friend.
-Yeah. Sorry.
Michael wants us to trust him.
I spoke to him the other night
about the whole Derek incident.
Dude was shook.
Talking about ethics
and all spiraling about human stuff.
I think he's on our side.
Or he's a supernatural demon
designed to torture people,
who got offered his dream job
and has flipped on us
like a ten-stone griddle-chip.
It's a large pancake.
[snapping fingers] Come on,
you can get these from context.
Maybe Michael jumped back
to the dark side, but I don't think so.
I think he's gonna help us escape.
I know it sounds crazy.
But if it weren't crazy,
they wouldn't call it "a leap of faith."
They would call it "a sit of doubting."
I never thought I'd be the one to say it,
but this is getting out of hand.
-We gotta go to the cops.
-What cops? Where do you think we are?
Before tonight's party,
I'd love to talk more
about your strategy for torturing Tahani.
I'm impressed you made her
fall in love with Jason.
She must be miserable.
Yeah. Humans make a lot of mistakes
when they're horny.
Ah, boss, give me a second here.
-What the here?
-Vicky...
My hard work paid off for you
and you're taking the credit.
Vicky, this can work out great
for both of us,
if we play our cards right.
Shawn thinks that
this is attempt number two, right?
If I tell him
you've been in charge of this version,
he'll find out there have been
hundreds of failed versions.
Oh, right.
And if that happens, we're all going down.
-So, spread the word.
-[sighs]
No one talks about the reboots.
Fine. You better make this right.
Mama want promotion. Ya heard?
[indistinct chatter]
[inaudible]
-Hello, you dummies!
-[all laughing]
This neighborhood was a labor of hate
for many people here.
So I thought that we should celebrate
with an art form that we literally
invented here in the Bad Place.
The comedy roast.
[all cheering]
[Michael] I see Jason Mendoza's here.
Jason might not be
the smartest guy in the world,
but he is the dumbest guy in the world.
[audience laughing]
Oh, Jason, buddy.
All you had to do was to keep quiet.
But you couldn't stop talking
about Kendall Jenner
or that dumb quarterback.
What was his name? Derek Bortles?
Always ranting about Derek Bortles.
Lucky for you, my friend,
Jaguars games are the only ones televised
in the Bad Place
because they suck!
[laughing]
No, they don't! All we need is a defense
and an offense and some rule changes.
Don't take it personally.
He has to put on a show
for the other demons.
Tahani Al-Jamil.
Elegance, grace, sophistication.
But enough about your sister!
[audience laughing]
You know what the worst moment
of Tahani's life was?
When the last song played
at one of her parties
and she would run off and cry
because she still hadn't won
her parents' approval.
[laughing]
You know the other worst moment
of Tahani's life?
Every other moment
of her empty, pointless life!
-[Michael exclaims]
-[audience laughing]
I see Eleanor Shellstrop is here.
Eleanor and I have a lot in common.
Here's how you tell us apart.
One of us is a manipulative demon
who's an expert
at making other people miserable,
and then the other one is me!
[laughing]
You thought you deserved a Medium Place
like Mindy St. Claire?
Are you kidding me? You're bad, Eleanor.
This is exactly the place you should be.
Not super funny for a roast, there, bud.
Oh, you want a joke?
You love Chidi
and Chidi doesn't love you back.
-Boom!
-[audience laughing]
Now that's funny
because it's very cruel and humiliating.
-You're one of my closest friends.
-Not now.
[Michael] "Speaking of Chidi,"
is something no one has ever said
because no one talks about Chidi,
because no one likes Chidi,
because he's so annoying about ethics.
Now, when you taught the trolley problem,
did you secretly wish that it could be you
who wound up under the trolley?
Because all your students did.
-Whoo-hoo!
-[audience laughing]
Whoa, Chidi, sorry, I got a joke
for you, bud. Uh, knock-knock.
Who's there?
You died alone because
you couldn't commit to anyone.
[laughing]
"You died alone because
you couldn't commit to anyone," who?
-No.
-Jason Mendoza!
[laughing]
Okay, that's all my time.
Let's tear this mother to the ground!
[all cheering]
So, maybe I was wrong
and Michael isn't on our side.
What up, fart sticks?
That was "She Hates Me" by Puddle of Mudd.
Coming up next,
"Grandma Got Run Over By A Reindeer."
-Idiots.
-[blows horn]
-We're going streaking! [screams]
-[cheering]
Ugh. The one time I think
someone isn't lying to me,
it bites me in the ash.
I guess Michael really did flip back
to the bad side.
Oh, does one think?
That roast was the meanest thing
I've ever seen
and I saw a waiter bring Russell Crowe
the wrong tea.
Well, we have no choice. We go to Shawn
and we say we'll trade
secret information about the reboots
if he'll go easy on us.
-[sighs]
-And if that doesn't work,
we try to free Janet
and go to Mindy's. Agreed?
Yeah. Michael sucks now.
He pretended to be our friend,
he's gonna torture us for eternity
and you know what the worst part is?
He's forgotten
my favorite football player's name.
-Definitely not the worst part.
-It is to me!
Blake Bortles is a cool name.
Derek Bortles is a dumb name.
-[dragon growling]
-[people screaming indistinctly]
[inaudible]
Hey, man. Have you told Shawn
how hugely important I was yet?
I will get to it. Promise.
Now you just relax, enjoy yourself.
Rip a cat in half. It's a party.
Come on!
-Hey!
-[exclaims]
What does Michael keep whispering to you?
Um, something, something, Vicky.
Something, something.
-Uh, can I braid your hair?
-No.
-Please.
-No. I got it.
-Hey!
-Ooh!
Help me get these bracelets
off Good Janet.
No. Shawn put them on for a reason.
I'm not overruling him.
-You're such a suck-up, Gayle.
-[scoffs]
-Can I braid your hair?
-No. I got it.
-Okay... [groans]
-Ow! Get your own bracelets, Victoria.
Okay, you fat dinks, the sun is up,
and we're about to close it down
with one last song.
"She Hates Me" by Puddle of Mudd
and "Grandma Got Run Over By A Reindeer"
played at the same time.
Honestly, I'm still partial
to the old-fashioned scorpion diapers,
but you've done great work here.
Can't thank you enough for everything.
-Shawn, wait.
-No--
I have some very interesting information,
about who is really responsible
for this neighborhood.
The humans are escaping.
It's Michael.
He's responsible for this neighborhood
and everything that's happening right now.
Bye!
-[sighs] I--
-Bad Janet!
What's cracking, nutbutts?
Call us another train, immediately.
Party's over.
[brakes screeching]
How did they get Janet's bracelets off?
It's impossible for a human to do.
It's like breathing underwater
or driving without texting.
Shawn, I don't wanna make any accusations,
but I accuse Vicky.
She asked me to help her
take Janet's bracelets off.
Oh, Vicky, you didn't.
She definitely did. She's jealous.
She's been trying to sabotage me
the entire time.
What? No. He's lying.
Okay, I did try to get the bracelets off,
but I couldn't!
Listen to yourself.
You sound crazy.
Normally, I would love hearing a man
tell a woman she's crazy, but I can't.
You aided the humans to spite Michael.
You're no demon.
You're a jerk.
Wait, this is a trick.
Michael is the traitor.
I bet they're still here.
This place stretches for a thousand miles.
Fine. Bad Janet?
What?
Scan the neighborhood, please.
No sign of humans,
but I did find something for Vicky.
What?
[farts]
[both chuckle]
-Bad Janet, great stuff as always.
-No, duh.
And as for you...
[Vicky] No, wait.
This is a PR disaster.
We have to keep it under wraps.
Get her on the train.
And if anyone else says a word
of what happened here to anyone,
you will be in a cocoon, just like Vicky,
and it is gooey in there.
How do we get the humans back
from Mindy's?
They bought themselves some time,
but we'll get them.
I'll start the extradition papers.
You stay here.
I want every trace
of this neighborhood erased.
[grunts] That was a bad idea!
That was so scary,
so many different times.
I hated that.
You guys!
I was so scared for you. [crying]
Told you he was on our side!
[crying] You're my friends
and I wanted to save you.
[Eleanor] Hey, it's okay, bud.
This is the best summer ever, you guys.
[Janet and Michael crying]
Oh.
Oh, Michael, we never doubted you.
Thank you, Tahani.
You're lying, right?
Yes. I doubted you very strongly.
But then I figured it out.
Kierkegaard, baby! Leap of faith.
It's better translated
as "a leap into faith."
You remembered.
-[Michael laughing]
-Can somebody explain what happened?
And can you guys be a tiny bit quieter?
I've been drunk on magnets all day
and I can literally hear
every sound in the universe.
Basically, Michael sent us a code
and we had to crack it.
-I figured out the first clue.
-No. I did.
-I was there, though.
-[Janet] Oh!
Blake Bortles is a cool name.
Derek Bortles is a dumb name.
Yes.
Derek Bortles is indeed a very dumb name.
It's a clue. There's no way Michael
would've forgotten that name.
You say it a million times a day.
-'Cause he's the best.
-He's not. Even I know that.
Michael was telling us to use Derek,
Janet's Derek, for something.
There were clues in the roast.
Everybody, quietly but quickly,
head to the train station.
Let's split up so we don't draw attention.
Ugh. You guys are the worst conspirators.
What else did Michael say in the roasts
that might be meaningful?
Tahani, do you remember?
Well, he said my entire life
was pointless and empty.
Yeah, but did he say anything
we don't already know?
Anything that stood out?
You know what the worst moment
of Tahani's life was?
When the last song played
at one of her parties,
and she would run off and cry
because she still hadn't won
her parents' approval.
That was odd.
A host never runs off
during the last song.
Because after it's over,
you're supposed to act surprised
when everyone drags you onstage
and showers you with applause.
Maybe Michael wanted us to wait
until the end of the party
when everyone is most distracted.
And use Derek to drive the train
because he has
some of Janet's powers. Janet?
Hi. Hey. Hey.
-[Eleanor] Janet?
-Yep?
You need to get Derek from your void.
Okay. Shoot, where's my void, again?
I forget.
Oh, yeah, it's everywhere.
Okay, hang on to your butt cheeks.
-[beeps]
-Ugh. Where is he?
-[objects clattering]
-Ow. Owie. [groans]
I'm never gonna find...
Oh, there he is.
-Derek.
-Hmm.
Derek, we need you to drive this train
and take us to Mindy St. Claire's house.
-Can you do that?
-[scoffs] Derek.
[all chuckle]
Wait. Nobody get on that train.
-Derek?
-Why not?
Because of what Michael said to me.
You thought you deserved a Medium Place?
You're bad, Eleanor.
This is exactly the place you should be.
Derek.
Michael wants us to stay here,
for some reason.
Eleanor, we have a train, a conductor
and a safe destination.
I'm going to tell you the same thing
I told Pippa Middleton
right before we went paragliding
in Gibraltar.
"Let's go." What? It's what I said.
Guys, leap of faith.
Michael said
we shouldn't get on that train.
Any minute now, those demons
are gonna come looking for us.
Where are we supposed to hide?
Oh, no!
Now, when you taught the trolley problem,
did you secretly wish that it could be you
who wound up under the trolley?
Because all your students did.
-Uh-uh.
-All aboard!
-[shushing]
-The train is here! It's a train!
Get on board.
-Actually, Derek--
-Derek.
You're gonna wait
until the last song of the night.
Derek.
And when you leave, you'll be flying solo.
Oh. Maximum Derek.
Derek headed off.
And when the new train arrived,
the four of us crawled underneath
before any of the drunk demons saw us.
That kept us from being detected
when Bad Janet scanned the neighborhood.
We fooled those mofos
like the chumps they are.
We got all four clues you left us.
Oh, that's great.
Actually, I left you more than 1,200 clues
because of how primitive your brains are,
but I'm glad you got enough
to figure it out.
How did you escape detection though?
I'm not ethically proud of this,
but I framed Vicky.
It was easy. I kept whispering things
into Janet's ear to make her paranoid.
I'm sorry. What did you whisper to me?
I don't remember.
[whispers] Something, something, Vicky.
Something, something.
What does Michael keep whispering to you?
Something, something, Vicky.
Something, something. [exclaims]
[Michael] And that made her
try to take Janet's bracelets off,
which framed her for the escape.
[all] Oh!
Guys, I want to apologize
for roasting you earlier.
I had to sell it
since everyone was watching.
It was funny, right?
-Absolutely not.
-The Tahani stuff was perfect. I mean, no.
Guys, let's just take a moment here.
[chuckles] They're gone.
Which means that we won
and might actually get a chance
to go to the real Good Place.
This is everything we ever wanted.
Speaking of which,
I really hope Mindy liked our present.
[knocking at door]
Who are you?
Derek.
"Thanks for helping us
all those times we showed up.
To repay you, here's a willing sex robot
and two duffel bags full of cocaine."
There are wind chimes
where my ding-dong should be.
[wind chimes tinkling]
-I can work with that.
-All right.