[Eleanor] You all right, chief?
You look like you lost
your lucky bookmark.
Oh, no! Did I?
[chuckles] It's fine. I got it right here.
It's just that
now that we're actually on the train,
heading to Bad Place headquarters,
this plan is starting to feel slightly...
completely insane.
-This is the only way to get to the Judge?
-I'm afraid so, yes.
See, the Judge exists
in a sort of neutral zone,
separate from the Good Place
and the Bad Place.
The only things there
are the Judge's quarters,
the accounting department
and the Janet Warehouse.
No, there's also an IHOP.
Oh! I'm gonna order
the Rooty Tooty Fresh 'N Fruity!
No, sorry, in this realm, IHOP stands for
"Interdimensional Hole of Pancakes."
You don't really eat these pancakes.
It's more like they eat you.
Okay. I'll get eggs, then.
So, the only way to get to the Judge
is through a portal,
which is smack dab in the middle of
the main office at Bad Place headquarters.
And the only way through the portal
is with one of these.
What is that? Is that jewelry?
Not that it matters.
It's just some jewelry I don't have.
[chuckles] Can I have it?
These pins are hard to come by.
Only upper management-types have them.
So, you guys will lay low
while I get us four more.
Janet doesn't need one because,
for portals, she counts as a carry-on.
I'm luggage.
I had Janet make you each
a Bad Place disguise.
And everyone who worked
in the neighborhood
has been sent back
to their previous departments.
So the chances of you
being recognized are very small.
I don't know. This plan seems complicated.
To be fair, you once said that
about an orange.
They don't make sense.
Apples, you eat their clothes,
but oranges, you don't?
Forget this plan.
I say we huck a Molotov cocktail
and [whooshes] run through the portal.
I think we should go with Michael's plan.
I'm telling you, Molotov cocktails work.
Any time I had a problem,
and I threw a Molotov cocktail...
Boom, right away,
I had a different problem.
He makes a strong case.
[theme music playing]
Okay, now you're all gonna need aliases.
Cool. I'm gonna be Diana Tremaine.
That was the name on my fake ID
in high school.
[chuckles] Her address was
123 Whatever Street, Canada City, Canada.
Arizona bouncers are the best.
Character work. Such fun.
I dabbled in a bit of acting
after university.
Mostly, I just stood around
while Baz Luhrmann threw glitter on me.
I shall be Rhonda Mumps,
and I work down at the hot dog factory.
You need to be specific.
There are nine
Hot Dog Torture Departments.
Making people into,
stuffing people with...
Stuffing people sounds fun.
Is that shoving them into vegan's throats?
Yes... throats.
-I know what my secret identity is.
-You can't be Blake Bortles.
-Fine. Then I'll be Jake.
-Don't say "Jortles."
Jortles! I work
in the Molotov Cocktail Department.
I thought you would be
more worried about this.
We've been knee-deep in demons
for 800 reboots now.
-Lying about who we are is second nature.
-[Michael] Huh.
-Chidi?
-I hate this. I hate lying.
-It's not permissible. I can't do this.
-[Michael] Oh, boy.
Jeez Louise. Looks like Chidi has
a real case of the Mondays, am I right?
[chuckles] Hey, pass the Nascar ketchup.
Hey, buddy.
Look, if you don't wanna lie
because it conflicts
with your moral principles, I get it.
-No one's gonna be mad at you.
-Really?
No, dumbass! I'm lying to you
to make you feel better.
See? Sometimes lying is awesome.
[gasps] Plus, I said "dumbass."
Oh, cursing, how I've missed you.
Look, Eleanor, our goal here is to appear
in front of a Judge
who is going to judge us.
What if I lie down here
and I lose 12 points,
then in front of the Judge
I'm 12 points short?
What if the Judge doesn't take our case
because we lied to get there?
Kant says that lying is always wrong.
I follow that maxim.
You can't even lie to demons?
They're trying to torture us!
We're behind enemy lines!
Principles aren't principles
when you pick and choose
when you're gonna follow them.
I won't lie about who I am.
Okay.
I understand and am cool with it.
-You're lying, aren't you?
-Yes. I wanna strangle you.
What even is this thing?
I hate suits.
They remind me of court,
and going to court,
and being my own lawyer against
the advice of the judge in court,
and getting immediately convicted.
I think you look nice.
I think you look sexy.
Here. I got you this
to help your disguise.
Whoa, a briefcase?
Take my credit card to the hedge fund.
I'll meet you at the martini store.
Oh, you're gonna get caught.
Give me the briefcase back. Thanks.
Aw.
Janet, you need to get in character, too.
I know you look like a Bad Janet,
but can you act like one?
I've gained new skills recently.
I learned how to be passive-aggressive.
Totally fine
that you guys haven't noticed.
Oh.
-[stutters] Let's practice.
-Okay.
I'll make a request,
and you give me
that patented Bad Janet attitude.
-Can I have a glass of water?
-Here you go.
No. Let's try again. Be mean.
Bad Janet, can I have a glass of water?
[straining] No. I would never
give you that, you... dumb person.
What's behind you?
-Nothing.
-Give it to me.
-It's a glass of water.
-Oh.
-And a backup glass. Oh, boy.
-Oh, boy.
Oh.
-It's okay, we'll keep working.
-Okay.
-[rails screeching]
-We're here.
[announcer] All trains today
are delayed by three hours.
Just like they are every day.
All passengers, you all suck
and you're ugly.
Keep walking. Keep your heads down.
Just act unnatural.
Hey, guys. Wait here while I go
get us some more of these pins.
-But what is this place?
-It's just a place.
An area or location.
It's pretty straightforward.
-"The Museum of Human Misery"?
-[Michael] Oh, yeah.
It's a torture museum.
Famous examples of bad behavior
and explanations
of the torture they earned.
-Is there a gift shop?
-Jason, this is hell.
Of course there's a gift shop.
It's the least horrifying room.
It's the Hall of Low-Grade Crappiness.
"First person to floss
in an open-plan office"?
Well, she deserves to be tortured.
She's a monster.
This was the safest place
I could think of.
No one ever comes in here.
Guys, if you do leave this room
you'll see things
that will haunt you for eternity.
Okay, back soon. Bye.
Hey, hey! Be careful. Okay?
"Be careful"?
Yeah.
Oh, Eleanor, are you worried about me?
Yeah, I'm worried.
'Cause you're
our ticket out of here, genius.
Don't go getting all goopy on me.
-Worry about them. I'll be fine.
-Okay.
[chuckles]
"First man to send
an unsolicited picture of his genitals."
[animatronic man] Heh. Heh. Heh.
"First waiter to approach a diner
with an empty plate
and sarcastically say,
'I guess you hated it.'"
"First white person to grow dreadlocks
and first person to call
Ultimate Frisbee 'Ultimate!'"
This dude rules!
[Petruchio] All right,
we've got a lot of work to do.
Why don't you set up the bar
over by that wall?
Why don't you roll off your mom
and do it yourself, you fat dink?
[both laughing]
Set up more tables.
We're expecting a big crowd.
You got it, you piece of... butt.
[whispering] Son of a bitch!
Still happy I can swear now,
but everything else about this
is very bad.
[indistinct chatter]
Hey, boss. I'm back.
Welcome home. Axe up.
Ow! New scent. "Transformers."
Yes. It makes you smell how
Transformers movies make you feel.
Still can't believe those jack-offs
got away. Really zips my tip.
-Yeah.
-Anyway,
I drew up some extradition papers
to get them back from Mindy's.
I'll take a few of my most trusted staff,
hop in the portal,
file those with the Judge,
quick stop for pancakes,
and then I'll head on back.
By the way, I'm gonna need four pins
for my crew.
This is very thorough. However...
Is that where we're putting
top priority files nowadays?
We won't need extradition papers.
Plans are already in motion to get
the humans back in a different way.
Ah.
[instrumental music playing]
Oh, man, this is not good.
This is not good!
We can't stand here in a group.
Looks too conspicuous.
I'll go with Tahani.
Chidi, go with Jason.
Jason's unearned confidence
lets him do all the talking
and you don't have to lie. Okay?
Come on, Diana, let's hit the bar.
I'm gonna get me a tall glass
of pipin' hot corn syrup
and a scooter,
so I can roll around the mall.
-[whispering] That's really good.
-Thank you.
-Hors d'oeuvre?
-Oh, what do you got?
Soul food from Maine,
bagels from Arkansas,
Hawaiian pizza, of course,
and egg salad from a hospital
vending machine in Azerbaijan.
-That.
-Have a terrible evening.
No way! Trent? Is that you?
Uh, who else could it be?
Come on, tap it out. Boom, boom.
What's up? I'm Chet.
Jake is my name,
Molotov cocktails is my game.
I think school is lame.
I got a tattoo of David Blaine! What!
Whoo! Tight! Ball tap! [laughs]
-Dip! Ball tap!
-Ow!
That's a firm ball tap, bro.
Anyway, your boy Trent and I worked
together in Partial Decapitations.
-When did you leave Decap? 800 years ago?
-Something like that.
I just joined a new department,
Toxic Masculinity.
We torture Internet trolls, frat dudes.
It actually started as a training program
to prep for when
the Girls Gone Wild dude gets here.
-Joe Francis?
-The one.
Legend!
[chuckles] Bro-hams, get over here
and meet my top dog, Trent.
Dude's a straight beast
when it comes to torture.
-'Sup, bro?
It's pretty choice
that we're running into you right now.
My top dog, Dirk, here,
he got stuck with a new case.
He can't crack it.
Hit 'em with it, D-money.
I'm trying to torture this guy, Brant.
Brant was a total lord.
He got kicked off of
Rob Gronkowski's party cruise
for throwing a lobster at a stripper,
and then he died doing a keg stand
in the back of a moving Jeep Wrangler.
Anyways, we run
a couple hundred torture scenarios.
None of them seemed quite right.
Think we can get you to crack this nut?
-Well, how can I say no?
-[all laughing]
Yeah, I know how I would say no.
I'd be all like, "No!"
But I can't.
You're so weird, Trent, man.
You're always so weird.
-Yeah.
-I love that about you.
Don't get me wrong,
I love shoving hot dogs into people,
but once you've dogged every hole,
you just start to feel like
you're repeating yourself.
I hear that, sister.
I'm gonna go take a dump.
You want me to grab you one?
-Nah, I'm good, thanks.
-Not even a little nugg?
-Nah, I'm a'ight.
-All right.
Damn, you're good at this.
Hang out with Johnny Depp enough,
you become pretty good at lying.
Like, "No, your whole thing
isn't exhausting at all!"
Hi, there...
you big, stinky, poop-face guys.
It's me, Good Janet.
I'm sorry I called you
big, stinky, poop-face guys.
That's okay.
Can you dig around a little bit
and find out what this event is
and how long it's gonna last?
I'd love to.
Punch your... teeth!
Hey. Hi. Teeth. Ugh.
[Michael] What's all this?
I was going to try to get the humans back
by going through the proper channels.
But then I remembered...
I'm a naughty bitch.
[all chuckle]
So, I sent a black ops team to Mindy's,
to extract them.
Nobody from the Bad Place is allowed
in Mindy's neighborhood.
You can't do that, Shawn. It's illegal.
Oh, no.
Guys, Michael says this is illegal.
I hadn't thought of that.
[all laughing]
That was sarcasm.
I had thought of that.
Listen, your experiment
blew up in our faces.
The example I made of Vicky ensured
everybody kept their mouths shut,
but we're not out of the woods
until those four are back in custody.
I rounded up some loyal friends
and took matters into my own hands.
Relax, Mike. This will all be over soon
and we can all head down to the museum.
The museum?
Yes. Your neighborhood, our neighborhood,
is being immortalized for its success.
It's all gonna work out.
I took the form of a 45-year-old white man
for a reason. I can only fail up.
-[alarm blaring]
-The team is in place. Let's do this.
Hey! So, those bro demons over there
think I'm some kind of great torturer,
and they want my advice
on how to torture someone.
Jason is stalling by ranking
MMA ring girls with them,
but I have to do something.
Eleanor, you're wearing glasses now.
Help me!
You know the answer, dude.
Lie your ass off.
If Rhonda can do it, you can.
I once shoved a hot dog
right down the throat
of the legendary John Wayne.
She even name-drops in hell.
I told you, lies have consequences!
I will have contributed
to someone's eternal torture,
because I disobeyed
a basic Kantian moral principle.
I'm gonna be sick.
I don't wanna go back to the bathroom.
They put mirrors in the toilet.
That makes you really confront
what you're doing!
Okay, okay. Sit down.
-Take a breath. Rub your lucky bookmark.
-[breathes heavily]
Hear me out.
What if lying is ethical
in this situation?
What if certain actions aren't universally
good or bad, like Jonathan Dancy says?
Jonathan Dancy?
Are you talking about moral particularism?
We never covered that.
-You read on your own?
-[scoffs]
You think just because
I'm a straight hottie
I can't read philosophy for fun?
-I--
-Look, moral particularism says
there are no fixed rules
that work in every situation.
Let's say you promised your friend
you'd go to the movies,
but then your mom
suddenly gets rushed to the ER.
Your boy, Kant, would say,
"Never break a promise.
Go see Chronicles of Riddick.
Doesn't matter if your mom gets lonely
and steals a bucket of Vicodin
from the nurse's closet."
-Real example?
-Yep.
But a moral particularist like me...
I'm one now. I just decided.
Would say, "There's no absolute rule.
You have to choose your actions
based on the particular situation."
Right now,
we are in a pretty bonkers situation.
I don't think I can change what I believe
just like that.
And I didn't think I would ever be
at a cocktail party in literal hell
lecturing my teacher/ex-lover
about moral particularism,
but life throws you curveballs, bro!
And need I remind you,
it was doing things your way
that made you end up here.
Man! Get back over there, dog!
[sniffs] Damn. You got that good stank.
Thanks. Back at you, bud.
Smash you later. Let's roll.
[indistinct chatter]
Hey, butt... Ass!
Butt-ass.
How long is this stupid event
supposed to last anyway?
They're unveiling the exhibit
in ten minutes,
then everyone'll get drunk
and poke each other with hot sticks,
and then it'll be over.
Farts.
Uh-oh.
[Shawn] Bad Janet? Walkie-talkie mode.
[electronic beep]
[operative] Now entering
Mindy St. Claire's house.
[laughs] This is so exciting!
I hope everyone gets hurt!
Living room is clear.
Entering the bedroom.
-[door opens]
-[Mindy] Oh, yeah!
-[Derek] Ow!
-[Mindy] Oh!
-[Mindy] God! This feels so weird.
-[Derek] Here we go.
[Mindy] Do some coke off my butt!
Wait! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Who are you guys?
[Derek] Oh, friends! Hi, I'm Derek.
Where are the humans?
And who is Derek?
Me is Derek. These are my wind chimes.
Oh, oh, oh.
My wind chimes like you.
[operative] The only people here
are Mindy St. Claire
and an unknown male
with a genital deformity.
The four humans are not here.
Where is Michael?
Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
-[Lance] Hey, there, Mike.
-Oh!
Hey, Lance. Looking good, buddy!
-Lose some weight?
-[Lance] I wish!
We need to find Michael,
and we need to be discreet.
You, search from
the Spastic Dentistry Department,
down through Disembowelment.
You, cover Children's Dance Recitals
through Holiday Weekend IKEA. Go.
Hey, hey, hey! Found him.
He was birddogging some tail.
What you got for me, Trent?
Well, peep this, dog.
You really wanna torture this dirtbag?
You give him books. I'm serious.
This one time I was assigned
this chick that I had to torture,
and I just couldn't figure it out.
And then I realized she hated books.
So I just gave her mad books to read,
around the clock.
The books, like, exploded?
No, no, no. They were just
regular moral philosophy books.
Everyone hates moral philosophers.
That is true.
I know it's wild, but sometimes
you gotta think outside the bun.
Sick Taco Bell ref.
-Very nice!
-But I don't know, man.
It sounds kind of lame.
This guy's the best? Really?
Yeah, maybe I don't know
what I'm talking... Ball tap!
[all cheering]
That's what you get for questioning Trent,
the torture master!
-He got you so bad!
-Yeah, he did. He did.
Nice job, bro. All right,
you've convinced me. I'll give him books.
Hey, you two.
Get your ugly necks over here.
Guys, I found something very bad.
We have to get out of here right now.
All right, everybody, gather around.
This is the moment
we've all been waiting for.
-What do we do?
-Just don't draw attention.
It'll be over in a second.
We can sneak out the door.
Feast your eyes on the newest exhibit here
at The Museum of Human Misery.
The residents of Neighborhood 12358W.
Oh, no.
Is that what they think
my hair looks like?
This game-changing experiment
chose four humans
and had them torture each other.
It's already led to major breakthroughs
in the future of our industry.
Obviously, we couldn't get
the actual four idiots
as they're off being tortured,
so we cooked up the next best thing.
-Wanna meet them?
-[audience] Yeah!
I'm Tahani Al-Jamil,
a vainglorious attention-seeker,
with enough jealousy to power Elon Musk's
underwater mansion,
-which I've been to, by the way.
-[all laughing]
I have, actually. It's remarkable.
-It's remarkable.
-[all laughing]
I'm Chidi Anagonye. Or maybe I'm not.
-I can't decide anything. Or maybe I can.
-[all laughing]
Ah. I can't decide. My stomach hurts.
[audience laughing]
What? They kinda nailed it.
I've heard you say all that stuff.
I'm Eleanor Shellstrop.
I mock others to distract myself
from the emptiness inside me.
That's a fair hit.
I'm Jason Mendoza. Duh!
-[audience laughing]
-That's me.
Hey, where've you been?
Oh, how do you smell loud and confusing?
No time to explain. We gotta go.
I got the travel pins.
Yo, that looks like my boy Trent.
And isn't that Rhonda Mumps?
-Come on!
-There he is.
-[Chidi] Uh-oh!
-And he's got the humans with him.
All right, let's just back up here.
What do we do?
This!
Jortles! Go!
Hey, Eleanor, thanks for the advice.
It was helpful.
Even though I had to say
words I don't like,
like "douche," "chick," and "peep this."
No problem.
I'm focused on running right now.
Right, I'm sorry!
Here. Put the pins on your lapels.
Okay. Okay.
Uh, you didn't give me a pin, man.
I don’t have one.
-Okay, hang on.
-Hey, where's Janet?
No time to wait for her.
You three go. Now. Now!
[gasps and squeals]
[grunts]
Portals!
-Any day now, man!
-[Shawn] Hey!
Hey, guess what?
I just solved the Trolley Problem.
Remember? The thought experiment
where you're driving the trolley
and you can either
plow into a group of people
or turn and hit one person? I solved it.
That's really great.
But I don't think now's the time--
The Trolley Problem forces you
to choose between two versions
of letting other people die.
And the actual solution is very simple.
-You sacrifice yourself.
-What does that mean?
-You look after the others. They need you.
-No.
[Shawn] Step away from the portal!
-Goodbye, Eleanor.
-No, no, wait, wait!
Hey, boss. What's up?