[Judge] So, Michael,
you're saying there's a new angle
I should consider in this case?
Love that. Major drama. [chuckles]
Spill the tea, sweetheart.
The premise of our system
is that a person's score
during her time on Earth
is final and inarguable.
But, because of my accidental experiment,
these four humans got better
after they died.
That's not supposed to be possible.
Over and over, I watched as they became
thoughtful and generous and caring.
And think about where they started.
Uh, Jason. Growing up in Jacksonville,
what did you do for fun
after school every day?
Me and my friends whipped
empty spray paint cans at flamingos.
And now he's so much better.
I was already good.
When I was six, I hit one on the butt.
Let the immortal beings talk, darling.
So they got better
in your little pretend world.
That doesn't prove anything
about what they were like on Earth.
No, see, I think it does prove something.
If I'm right, the system
by which we judge humans,
the very method we use
to deem them good or bad,
is so fundamentally flawed
and unreasonable
that hundreds of millions of people
have been wrongly condemned
to an eternity of torture.
Damn! That was intense.
Look at my arm, y'all.
Look, I got goose bumps.
-Huh. Yeah.
-Doesn't happen very often.
[theme music playing]
Wow. So you saw your parents in the test?
Yes, and I immediately fell right back
into my old pattern.
Desperately trying to impress them
and earn their admiration.
Then I heard this little voice
in my head saying,
"Tahani, don't do this."
The voice in your head sounds like
the old lady from Downton Abbey?
Oh, yes, sorry.
Maggie Smith is my godmother.
Anyway, I took a deep breath,
told them I ate a Cheeto and walked away.
Man, you have made so much progress.
I'm proud of you, hot stuff.
Whatever progress I have made,
it's because you and I have become mates.
That's British for friends.
-No, I know.
-Oh.
Man, think about everything
that's happened to us.
We died, Michael tortured us,
we teamed up with him, we escaped.
We went through the portal,
the Judge ruled against us,
then Michael showed up.
This has been one of
the craziest years of my life. [chuckles]
-One of?
-Yeah.
I'm not sure what I would do
if one more insane thing happened.
Hi, Jason. I love you.
Oh, word?
Word. I've been avoiding telling you.
My excuse was that I needed time
to evaluate my complex feelings,
but that was a rationalization.
This might be the last time
I ever get to talk to you, so there it is.
I love you. And I hereby
stop avoiding this topic
and rationalizing it by saying
the situation's complicated.
Or that my brain is grinding
like a fork in a garbage disposal.
All right, whatever.
You're not really a part of this, Chidi.
[Jason] Hey, guess what.
I think I love you, too, girl.
I'm not a girl.
I'm also not just a Janet anymore.
I don't know what I am.
Hey, man. What's up?
Hot diggity dog!
Oh, no. Now the thing I said
right after we kissed will always be,
"Hot diggity dog."
Whatever. It was an honest reaction.
I stand by it.
Hi, guys, couple quick announcements.
Would anyone eat chips and guac
if I put it out?
It's good. It's homemade.
No takers? A'ight.
Second thing, we figured out a plan
to save your souls.
For the time being, the Judge is gonna
put you in your own Medium Places,
like Mindy St. Claire.
And while you're there, I'll keep working
every angle I can think of
to get you guys into
the Good Place for real.
This is great. So we'd all be together?
Oh, no, that's the thing
about Medium Places.
It has to be tailored
to what's medium for the individual,
so if you're all together,
it ain't medium.
How much time will we be alone?
Hard to say. Uh, could be a month.
Could be a million years.
So, between a month and a million years.
-Yeah. Somewhere in there.
-Give or take.
[Michael] Come on, you guys.
I know this isn't perfect,
but I need more time to build my case.
And it's either this
-or back to the Bad Place.
-Yeah.
I'll say it. Both those options suck.
Sorry if that's blunt,
Your Honor, but it's true.
Also, Chidi laid one on me,
so I'm kinda dizzy. [chuckles]
You two kissed? Hot diggity dog.
That's what I said.
The point is, we've all gotten better.
Why should we have to go live alone
in a boring void
because of a messed-up system?
How is that justice?
Okay, slow your roll there,
Erin Brockovich.
First of all,
y'all didn't get good enough
to pass the tests I just gave you.
Second, I still believe
that the only reason
that you improved
in Michael's fake neighborhood
is because you thought there was a reward
at the end of the rainbow.
You're supposed to do good things
because you're good,
not because you're seeking moral dessert.
And I still believe
that they would've become good people
if they'd just gotten a...
A push in the right direction.
Oh, no.
-No. Nope. Absolutely not.
-It's a little crazy.
"A little crazy"? It's looney tunes.
-What are they talking about?
-No idea.
It sets a very dangerous precedent.
It's only four people.
And it's clearly the best way to see
if bad people can become good
without knowing anything
about what's waiting in the afterlife.
[Jason] Shotgun.
Whatever they're talking about,
if there's a shotgun, I call shotgun.
-It's never gonna work.
-If it doesn't,
-then they go right back to the Bad Place.
-[sighs]
No one gets hurt, except them.
Forever. And me, I assume, also forever.
[clicks tongue]
Mmm...
[grunting]
-Okay, let's do it.
-Yes. [chuckles]
I don't know why. I'm just feeling funky.
But there have to be strict rules.
Otherwise, the results will be tainted.
And I reserve the right
to change my mind at any point.
About what?
Would someone who's not an eternal being
please explain to me what the--
[Judge clicks fingers]
[man] Why are you like this?
Excuse me? "Why am I like this?"
You don't know me, dude.
You don't know what I'm like.
Look what you made me do, jagoff.
[sighs]
-Look out!
-Uh-oh.
[gasps]
Holy crap.
I just almost died.
She needs to know what was said
that's so unfair.
[girl on TV] First of all,
this is just yesterday...
God, Eleanor. Take longer next time.
Oh, you look like crap.
I was outside the supermarket arguing
with that little environmental twerp.
-Ugh, I hate that guy.
-[Brittany] Really?
That skinny little hippie body
kinda turns me on.
-Gross. [chuckles]
-[Eleanor] Guys, listen.
I dropped the margarita mix.
And when I went to pick it up,
a bunch of shopping carts came
right at me and I was frozen.
And then someone pushed me out of the way
and the carts got demolished by a truck.
I mean, I could've died.
Oh, my God.
Whoa. That's crazy.
So is the margarita mix gone?
[Val] I had a near-death
experience recently.
You know that old warehouse
that burned down last month
and four people died?
That building is right by my old dentist.
If I still went to that dentist
and had an appointment that day,
I would've been like right near there.
I was in Syracuse, New York,
two weeks before 9/11.
-No way!
-Yeah, 14 days.
[Val] I can't believe we all almost died.
[Eleanor] My name is Eleanor Shellstrop,
and I think I might be a monster.
I'm rude. I'm selfish. I cyber-bullied
Ryan Lochte until he quit Instagram.
But something happened to me today,
and from now on I'm gonna try to become
a better, kinder, more generous person.
Hey. Can I use your credit card?
-You know what? Yes, you can.
-Cool.
It's for porn. I already used it.
Hey, you look happy.
Did you get laid last night?
I didn't. Tried. Hard,
with this chick that
I followed into a yoga class,
but she wasn't into it.
Maced me right in the eyes.
Stung like hell.
What was I saying? Oh, yeah. Hey.
Listen, dude. What you're doing here,
selling fake medicine to people,
tricking them, is wrong.
Yeah. And?
I can't be a part of it anymore.
I'm trying to be a better person.
As long as I work here--
Yeah, whatever, you quit. Who cares?
Gimme your company ID.
Thank you. And your parking pass...
and your panties, please.
-Dude!
-What? Come on, I had to try.
By the way, technically,
that is not sexual harassment.
She doesn't work here anymore.
-You're wearing a wire?
-Yeah.
Company's being investigated for fraud,
so I'm helping the feds
bring everyone down.
Good timing on your part.
Dude, get help.
I'm becoming a better person.
You should, too.
Eleanor, do you wanna come
to Lauren's baby shower?
Do you want to chew
on my ass-ortment of brownies
I will be bringing
to Lauren's baby shower?
[stutters] Sure.
Do you have a second to talk
about the environment?
Hey. Remember me?
Ah! Don't hurt me. My bones are brittle.
I have a calcium deficiency.
No, I'm not gonna hurt you, man.
I came to apologize.
-There, I did it. I apologized.
-No, you didn't.
Yes, I did, ass face.
[clears throat] Nope, you're right.
I didn't.
I apologize for being mean to you,
like, a thousand times.
There's really no excuse.
-Thanks. Apology accepted.
-Okay.
Uh, what's happening? I'm scared.
Hey, I'm on kinda a self-improvement kick.
Could you help me?
Teach me to get horny
for the environment or whatever?
Hey, everyone. This is Eleanor.
She's joining the team.
[all cheering]
-[woman] Welcome!
-Nice to meet you. Hi.
[machines clacking]
All right, Eleanor.
[Janet gasps]
♪ There is a sun among the remnants ♪
♪ Of all our words
That's left unsaid ♪
♪ And when the truth
Lies in our direction ♪
♪ Do we work it through
Or lose our heads ♪
♪ Maybe, maybe, maybe we're strong ♪
♪ Maybe, maybe, maybe we're wrong ♪
Mmm. Babes, get in on these nachos.
They're delish.
I'm actually trying to eat vegetarian.
Ew! Why?
Is it because you feel bad
for all the little animals
with their cute little faces
because people stuff them in a tiny cage
so we can eat them?
-[Brittany chuckles]
-Yeah. That's exactly why.
[chuckles] Okay, guys,
um, can I say something for a second?
-I love you.
-Aw...
[Val] I do. I went
through a rough time last year
with the whole Dress Bitch thing
and people
selling t-shirts with my face on them,
but you two stuck by me.
-I love you, you dumb sluts. Come on.
-Aw! [chuckles]
Okay, there's probably something
we should tell you.
Or not. We could also not.
We have to. It's the right thing to do.
I tore your dress.
And then I lied about it.
And then Brittany and I were the ones
who made and sold the T-shirts.
But we did not keep the money.
Yes, we did. We kept it all.
And I'm really sorry.
Okay.
-That took a lot of courage to admit.
-Mmm-hmm.
-And I admire your honesty.
-[sighs]
You stupid skank!
How could you do that to me?
I hate you!
You're both disgusting hogs and I want you
to move out of my apartment forever!
Literally, starting right now!
I'm still glad we told the truth.
Cool.
[grunts]
Okay, steamed vegetable medley
and ice water.
Can I just get the check?
And can you throw
these plants in the trash?
♪ Such a long time now ♪
♪ We're doing battle
With our own familiar inhibitions ♪
♪ Far away from home ♪
♪ Our trusty compass fails to find
Our strange and new position ♪
♪ Maybe, maybe, maybe we're strong ♪
♪ But maybe, maybe, maybe we're strong ♪
♪ But maybe, maybe, maybe we're wrong ♪
[sighs] Damn it.
-They're suing you?
-This chick is claiming she has whiplash.
She wasn't in the car when I hit it.
This is on you. You should've pretended
you didn't see it and walked away.
Like everyone else does.
I know. I've hit your car six times
and never said anything.
But I'm trying to be good.
[laughing]
How is that working out for you?
[machines clacking]
[knocking on door]
It's open, dummy!
Eleanor, where have you been?
Oh, hey, man. Sorry,
it's been a crazy month, you know?
Moving was a hassle,
and I'm in the middle of a lawsuit,
and I ate vegetables for the first time,
and I got diarrhea for a week.
I know we don't pay a lot,
but this is a job,
and we need to know we can count on you.
We're meeting tonight
to discuss strategy for the--
[Brittany] Dude, dude, dude...
Oh, sorry to interrupt
whatever boring crap this is,
but you need to get dressed.
I got tickets to Taylor Splift,
the Taylor Swift reggae cover band.
They're terrible.
It's going to be amazing. [chuckles]
Hmm.
Yeah, that sounds like more fun.
I'mma do that.
-Eleanor!
-What?
What? I've been nothing but good
for six months,
and all I have to show for it
is this crummy apartment,
a lawsuit, a loose caboose
and an overdrawn bank account.
Being good is for suckers.
What do you even get out of it?
A feeling of fulfillment in your soul.
Gross. That's the grossest sentence
I've ever heard. Okay?
I quit.
Eat my farts, Benedict Cumberbatch.
Whew! I still think he's hot.
I guess,
in a sick Victorian boy kind of way.
Ooh, yeah. I want to feed him soup.
[Eleanor] So tell me
about the new business.
We sell classes
at a for-profit university,
and the classes train people
how to sell supplements.
So it's a Ponzi scheme
within a Ponzi scheme.
-That sounds dicey.
-Oh, it's super dicey.
But I'm in witness protection,
so, technically,
I can't be convicted of any crime.
That's definitely not true,
but I also don't care.
Which one's my desk?
[machines clacking]
[sighs] You realize
what the problem is, right?
But there's no way to help.
[laughing]
I'm only giving that guy three stars
'cause he didn't let me stick my head
out the moon roof.
Yeah! Dude, my boyfriend just texted.
His wife's out of town,
so I'm gonna head over there. [kisses]
What? That's lame.
Boo!
[Brittany] Happy birthday!
Hello, bartender.
One alcohol drink, please.
It's my birthday if you wanna
give it to me for free. [chuckles]
I always say that,
but it actually is my birthday. [chuckles]
Last year, on my birthday I almost died,
and then I did a bunch of stuff
that was good, but weird,
and then I stopped, and now I'm here.
-Sounds like you had a pretty crazy year.
-Hmm.
Want to talk about it?
And in the end, Anthony Anderson
and Jerry O'Connell
start a successful shampoo company,
and you see the kangaroo
jumping around Australia.
[laughing]
That is the plot
to the movie Kangaroo Jack.
-Why did I tell you that?
-It's unclear.
You know, the thing is the problem
really with being a do-gooder?
-What's that?
-No one cares.
I mean, some people care a little bit.
The twerpy little twerps
from the environmental place, they care,
but I was a good person for six months.
That's like five years.
And it felt okay,
but not as good as I thought it would.
And what did I get for it?
Ah, see? Now you're talking
about moral dessert.
Exactly.
-Wait, I am? What?
-Moral dessert is the concept
that if you act with virtue,
you deserve a reward.
Right. If I'm not gonna get rewarded
somehow with a tiara
or one of those diagonal award belts...
-Sash.
-Sure.
Then why should I do good things?
You know, I had a friend that said
whenever she was doing something bad,
she'd hear this little voice in her head.
Distant little voice saying,
"Come on, now, you know this is wrong."
And then when she started
doing good things,
that voice went away. It was a relief.
Your friend sounds like she's one pickle
short of a pickle party. [chuckles]
She was a little rough around the edges,
but she was also a really good person.
When she tried.
See, I think that little voice
was her conscience
trying to guide her
in the right direction.
I gotta go home. What do I owe ya?
The real question, Eleanor,
is what do we owe to each other?
What? Did I sell you a drink?
Am I a bartender?
[chuckles] Drinks are on me.
Good luck.
Ow!
[machines clacking]
-Anybody notice I was gone?
-Nope.
[laptop chimes]
[Chidi through speakers]
What do we owe to each other?
That is the question
Tim Scanlon asked decades ago,
and it is the question I will try
to answer over the next three hours.
Ugh, no, thanks.
[Chidi] We all have a voice in our head.
That voice doesn't tell us what to do
or not do,
but it does warn us
when we do things
that don't feel good or right.
The difference between...
...reasonable.
What does it mean
to be a reasonable person?
I may have a different definition
of reasonable...
So why do it, then?
Why choose to be good every day
if there is no guaranteed reward
we can count on,
now or in the afterlife?
I argue that we choose to be good
because of our bonds with other people
and our innate desire
to treat them with dignity.
Simply put, we are not in this alone.
Hi, dog bait. Didn't you get my message?
Let's go. Time is booze. [chuckles]
Yeah, no, thanks.
I'm going somewhere else.
-G'day, where you headed?
-Saint John's University, please.
No worries.
[machines clacking]
-Hi.
-I'm sorry. Office hours are on Tuesday.
Oh, I'm not a student.
Are you Chidi Ana... Kendrick?
Anagonye. And, yes.
From the long, nerdy video about
the voice that tells you to be good?
From the Keswick Foundation lecture series
on practical applications
of ethical theory, yes.
Great. Hi, my name is Eleanor Shellstrop.
Can we talk?
[machines clacking]
Okay. Here we go.