Michael, a demon
has infiltrated the group.
Not just any demon.
Trevor is a diabolical, sadistic
agent of evil.
He might just be the single most
dangerous creature in the universe.
Who wants lemon bars?
It's my nana's recipe
and they are just sinful.
Love 'em on my lips,
but hate 'em on my hips,
-if you know what I mean.
-All right, new guy.
Comin' in strong with free dessert.
You must be Eleanor,
the reason this is all happening.
I am. It's so nice to hear someone say,
"Eleanor, you're the reason
this is all happening,"
who isn't a judge in small claims court.
Thank you for this, Eleanor.
It's a wonderful thing you've done.
[Eleanor] Mmm.
Happy to help you out, buddy.
Oh! We're doing a long hug.
-[sobbing]
-Are you crying?
I'm sorry. I'm just so happy to be here,
if that makes sense. [sniffles]
[Chidi] Okay, the five of us
narrowly avoided death.
The operating theory of this experiment
is that a second...
[theme music playing]
So, I give them ethics problems
and we scan their brains,
and we get a sense
of their baseline moral instincts.
Right. Then, I'll show them pictures
that trigger memories
of their near-death experiences.
We'll scan again
and see if we get a different result.
For example, I'll show Jason
pictures of a safe, a snorkel
and whip-it canisters.
Got it. Also, what a grim death
that would've been.
Darling, do you remember all the rules
about what can and cannot be worn
inside an MRI?
More specifically,
what if one's brassiere is very thin,
but also very pure gold?
I don't know, but I'm in a similar situash
because the sports bra I'm wearing
is kind of rust-colored
underneath the armpits,
so I guess we'll roll the dice together.
Hey, Eleanor, do I have
the right phone number for you?
You haven't responded
to any of the dank memes I've sent.
Oh... Yeah, I...
'Cause I was laughing too hard to reply.
Okay, what's your fave?
'Cause mine's "Damn, Daniel--"
-"Back at it again with the white Vans!"
-[laughs]
Should we get started, maybe?
[Jason] Oh, Mrs. Teacher?
For my turn, is there any way to get,
like, extra radiation?
There is no radiation in an MRI,
but why do you ask?
-Uh... No reason.
-[Eleanor] Jason.
-What do you got in your hand there, bud?
-Nothing.
Is it a spider?
-Yes.
-Do you think taking a spider
in an MRI machine
will give you super powers?
Hey, it might work.
He already bit me a bunch of times,
and gave me the power to swell up my hand.
[Tahani] Oh, my God!
What?
-Trevor.
-Hey, Mikey.
Fancy seeing you down on Earth,
completely illegally.
Sweet outfit. Dick Tracy called.
He said you're a buttface
and he's been plowing your mom.
Yeah, well,
Dick Tracy called me too, first,
and he said he was about to call you,
and say a lie about me
that was actually true about you, instead.
Whatever. What are you doing here, Trevor?
Shawn hacked the Judge's system
and we caught you cheating,
getting your four little cockroaches
to meet up.
What, you think we were just
going to sit around in the Bad Place
blowin' beefers while you're down on Earth
boning us in the meathole?
So why didn't Shawn just go to the Judge
and turn me in?
Because this way's more fun, knucklenuts.
First of all, I'm currently formulating
a better comeback to your Dick Tracy burn,
and it's gonna devastate you.
Second, you're too late,
because when I did this experiment
in my neighborhood,
every time Eleanor asked Chidi for help,
their bond became unbreakable,
and the entire group improved.
No, you're right. There's no way
I'll get one of these bozos
to drop out of an unpaid,
rigorous academic study,
especially when they're doing it with me,
their over-eager new best friend.
Well, I should head back.
You want to come with?
Oh, right, they've all seen you already,
so you can't show your face to them again,
so you're powerless to stop me.
Later days, dingus.
Dick Tracy called back on his watch phone
and said you better watch out.
[softly] Shoot. A second too late.
Okay, Simone's gotta analyze the scans,
so why don't the rest of you head home?
Good first day, everyone.
Hey, teach, um,
do you think maybe we could continue
the one-on-one lessons on the side?
I feel like last week
I had my own personal ninja master,
and now I'm taking tai chi
with a bunch of farting housewives.
Between the new project and my classes,
I won't have time.
But this is way better.
You're still gonna learn a lot,
and you'll have a fun group of people
to study with outside of class.
-But--
-[Trevor] Hey, gang.
I just had a neat idea.
Let's all go sightseeing.
-Dope!
-[Trevor] Yeah.
We can check out Sydney,
get to know each other, bond.
What do you say, E Street Band?
Ya up for a Segway tour of
[in Australian accent] Australia, mate?
This is a knife on the barbie. [chuckles]
Cool idea. I'm just worried
that maybe... it's too cool?
I think I'm just gonna find
the nearest bar,
have one or eight drinks and hit the hay.
Even better. We'll all go bend an elbow.
[normal] Actually, I know
the perfect place for homesick Americans.
[in Southern accent] Hi, dudes.
Welcome to the Cowboy Skyscraper Buffet.
Oh, hey, can we get the Florida table?
They absolutely nailed the swamp stench.
[normal] Oh. Someone's seated there.
But if you purchase
our Manifest Destiny package for $30,
you can have anyone you want
forcibly removed from the table.
We'll just sit anywhere.
[in Southern accent] When your
table's ready, this gun will go off.
I think this is real.
[Trevor] So, listen up, y'all.
I was so excited to join the group
that I made sweatshirts.
You get a sweatshirt.
-You get a sweatshirt.
-I get a sweatshirt.
"The Brain-y Bunch."
[Jason] Awesome! I love being on teams.
And if we're on a team now,
we need nicknames.
Optimus, Bumblebee, Jazz... Uh, Megatron.
That's what you can each call me.
Now we need nicknames for you guys.
Oh, this is the best!
I'm gonna get the first round,
and we are all gonna toast to Eleanor,
the reason we're all here! Yay, Eleanor!
-Eleanor!
-[all cheering]
Well, if you guys are celebrating,
I recommend the jalapeño poppers.
Hi, there. I'm Janet.
I'll be taking care of you tonight.
Can I get you started with some drinks?
Our specialty cocktail tonight
is the 4th of July.
It's half an apple pie,
blended with Southern Comfort
and Coca-Cola,
served in a Chevy hubcap. [chuckles]
Why don't you just go get us
a round of beers?
Of course. Here you go.
[chuckles] Sorry.
I will go physically pick those up,
I guess,
and then walk them back here
with my feet. [chuckles]
But just so you know,
I will be here all night,
watching everything that you order.
So, Ellie baby, brainstorm.
We should get a house.
Me, you, Tahani, Jason.
We should all go in together on a place.
-Roomies!
That is... technically, an idea.
I think it would be supes fun.
We could play pranks on each other...
-No.
-...for my vlog.
We could do one of those ice bucket
challenges that...
-I don't think so.
-...I sent you.
Or maybe just a Harlem Shake?
I like to cook and I have been...
-Please, stop.
-...dying to experiment with...
-Please stop now.
-...Jamaican food, man.
[in Jamaican accent]
I like the Jamaican food.
Listen to the reggae and smoke da joints.
[normal] That's a Jamaican accent.
Come on, come on, come on!
-[softly] Hey, how's it going?
-Not good, Michael.
I don't have my powers.
I can't summon things.
Dictionary. Spaghetti.
Jet Ski. Giraffe. Gah!
Look what I've been reduced to.
Humans only live 80 years,
and they spend so much of it
just waiting for things to be over.
I'm all out of sorts down here, too.
I'm bad at lying now.
That used to be my thing.
And every part of my body
is either too dry or too wet.
It's worse for me, man.
Ever since we walked through that portal,
my knowledge has stopped updating.
The instant before we left,
a man in Caracas, Venezuela,
named Raul Benitez
was eating a ham sandwich.
Did he finish it?
I don't know and it's making me crazy.
I gotta find him.
Janet, focus on the mission.
We have to get Trevor
away from the humans.
Okay.
I am so glad you came out with us, man.
I just assumed you would think
it's unprofessional to be friends
with the subjects of your study.
No, I never thought that.
I mean, I kind of do now.
Should I not be socializing?
I'm sure it's fine. I mean,
how much harm could it possibly do?
Good point.
Such a good point that I'm gonna go
think about how good a point that is,
over there, by myself,
for several minutes. Excuse me.
Hey, El-Train, you think
with all these new Star Wars movies,
they'll finally make a new Spaceballs?
I'm sorry, I'm getting a text
and I have to take this.
Okay, everybody, here are your beers,
and here is yours...
Oh, no! Oh!
I guess you should go to the bathroom
or maybe go home and never come back.
No worries, I made extra sweatshirts.
Besides, we're having
too much fun to leave.
Hey, speaking of fun, I know this
super-fun drinking game we could play.
Every time one of you says something
that the other can't relate to,
you both drink.
Could be fun.
I once played a drinking game
with Ryan Reynolds and Blake Lively
at their macrobiotic farm
with a particularly robust batch
of homemade kombucha.
Do I have to drink
for every word I don't know?
Up to you. Just drink.
Hey. What happened with Chidi?
And where's Eleanor?
This is all moving too fast!
Can we just take Trevor out?
I don't know if he can die, but I could
drop a steamroller on his head.
Aw, darn it. I can't summon things.
I guess I could kick him
with my soft feet? Earth sucks.
You stay on Trevor,
keep interfering with his plan, all right?
I'm gonna do my librarian act
and nudge Chidi back to the table.
-[Trevor] Ah...
-[Tahani] Yay!
Yummy!
You gotta relax, man.
You're off the clock.
It's just a simple drink with friends
at the world's worst restaurant.
No, but Trevor's right.
I might skew the study
by fraternizing with the subjects.
We can be colleagues.
Associates is pushing it.
And by even having this conversation,
you're becoming my confidant.
I can't have that.
Geez, I kinda thought
that before everyone else showed up,
you and I were becoming actual friends.
Oh, no! You're right. What have I done?
Okay, okay. I'm gonna go to the bar
and get you a hot tea.
-Okay.
-Or a regular-temperature Xanax.
-Mmm.
-Try not to fall apart.
[in Australian accent] Professor Anagonye?
Oh, yeah, I thought I recognized you.
It's me, the librarian, from the library.
Oh! Right. Hi. Sorry. Uh... I was just
in the middle of something here.
Well, maybe I can help.
You know what I like to do
in situations like these?
I haven't told you anything
about what I'm going through.
Do that first.
Then, I'll tell you what I do
in situations such as the one
you're about to describe.
I've been in every situation
because I'm a librarian.
Hit me. Go ahead.
Mmm.
Ah... [laughs]
I'm tired.
Does anybody want a gallon of water
to sober up?
[Trevor] No, thanks, sweetheart. I just
called a car for these two love birds,
so why don't you just bring us the check?
Oh, and you should smile more.
You'll get bigger tips.
Gosh, you're pretty.
No, you're pretty. Pretty beautiful.
If you ask me, Chidi,
you need to get back over there,
you know, spend time with the team.
Though we do have a saying
in the library game, um...
"There's only room for one male subject
in an academic study,
so keep the one who got there first."
-Catchy.
-Gotta go now.
The closest thing
I could find to herbal tea
was a root beer
I had them throw in the microwave.
You know what? Don't drink that.
I think I'm just gonna head home.
But you can go
and spend time with the others.
Yeah, man,
that's not really what I signed up for.
I mean, Tahani is eh.
But Jason, woof.
And Trevor, blech.
They're not the reason
I flew all the way from Arizona. You are.
I'm sorry,
but this is just how it has to be.
[stammers] I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey, E-Dog, get over here.
It's trivia night.
First-round questions
are all about Logan Paul.
And you know I'm Lo-gang for life.
[softly] Go put your head
up your own butt.
-What?
What?
[laughing]
Oh.
Don't you buttnecks ever give up?
No, and what are you
even doing in a bathroom?
You're a demon, you don't... need it.
I like the smells,
and I like putting my hands in the toilet,
so everything I touch
gets a little bit of poop on it.
Hey, you guys see what I did out there?
I am so good,
I got Eleanor to leave a bar early.
Chidi's melting down.
Jason and Tahani just left together.
If they hook up, she's on
the first private jet out of here.
This was too easy.
It's gonna take a lot more than that
to break up this group.
Why don't you give up, Trevor?
As long as we're here,
you'll never succeed.
Maybe, but how long will that take?
I mean, at some point,
the Judge will find out
that you're not in your little room
watching ticker tape. Right?
Tick, tick, tick, tick.
But, hey, may the worst demon win.
Good luck, Mikey.
Ah! Poop hands! I can't believe
you fell for that. [laughs]
Are you all right?
You didn't sleep at all last night.
Yeah, I got a solid eight minutes.
Not consecutively, but still, it's fine.
You're not even that blurry.
You gotta take it easy, man.
I mean, you're not sleeping.
Your eye is twitching.
This study has to be airtight,
and this ethical question of friendship
with the subjects is weighing on me.
I've done a million of these things.
I promise I'll warn you
if you cross any lines.
I don't want to come
anywhere near those lines.
I have been waiting my entire career
for the right thesis
and I am not going to blow it.
I have to keep this professional.
Fine, but you need to get some rest.
This morning, you bit into a raw egg
like it was an apple.
I thought it was hard-boiled.
Yeah, but still, the shell.
This is the best
secret-friend handshake, bro.
And it goes...
Attention, everyone. Do not look at me.
[chuckles] Oh. I don't know what to do.
I am both overhung and humiliated
by my uncouth comportment last night.
Please accept
these formal letters of apology.
Further apologies for their appearance.
I just couldn't find a proper calligrapher
at 5:00 in the morning.
So, what happened
to you two love birds last night, huh?
-Frankly, it is none of your business.
-Oh. Sorry.
But Jason was a perfect gentleman
last night.
Thank you so much
for getting me home safely.
I wouldn't blame you should you
ostracize me for my boorish behavior.
You weren't boring.
You were fun.
Crazy story. After you got into the cab,
I forgot where I lived,
but then I looked across the street
and there was a motel.
And behind that, there was a dumpster.
I slept in a dumpster.
Jason.
No, no, no, it was fine.
And it was super fun getting to know you.
You're the fanciest person I know,
next to my friend Ronnie,
who drives a limo.
He's in limos all the time.
Aw. What a life.
Right. As soon as Eleanor gets here,
we'll begin.
Bad news, prof.
Eleanor might not be coming.
She bailed right after you did last night.
Seemed like she was having second thoughts
about being a part
of the Brain-y Bunch, so...
Oh, well, that's disappointing...
[stammers] in terms of
how it affects the study.
But we press on, like professionals.
[sighs]
-Hey, do you think I should--
-Yeah.
And I already called you a car because
you should not drive. It's outside.
Thanks.
Where's outside?
[knock on door]
Hey, man.
-Are you okay?
-Sorry.
Uh, literally one second ago,
I was at the front desk.
Don't know where I got this. [laughs]
Anyway, are you coming to class?
Eh...
I don't think the group thing is for me.
I'm better when it's one-on-one,
and we're both looking at our phones,
and I don't know the other person,
and we don't talk.
I might just head back to Arizona.
[sighs]
Listen.
My whole life has been
a torture chamber of indecision.
And now, I'm finally on the path
to understanding why,
and the only reason that's happening
is because you walked into my office,
and you said
you wanted to be a better person.
That was really brave.
Now, I know we barely know each other,
but, please,
could you give me three months?
Can you give me three months?
I am asking you as a friend.
See, I just told you I don't like talking.
That whole thing could've been sent
in a text that I pretended I never saw.
[sighs]
Fine. You did good at talking.
I'll come back to class.
Come in! No?
-I'm gonna drive you back.
-Okay.
Hey, Dick Tracy called.
He said that I was right about Eleanor
and Chidi having an unbreakable bond.
I don't think you understand
how that joke works.
Yeah, that doesn't matter.
We won. That's the point.
You won squat.
We're gonna get 'em eventually.
I'll just keep chipping away
till one of them bails.
These four humans
are all I care about in the universe.
And there is nothing, and I mean nothing,
that's gonna come between me--
Oh. Cool. You're all together.
The Judge wants to see you.
Now? Right now?
-Um... Like, all of us, or--
-Yup.
So, this is Earth, huh?
Whoo.
Pretty cool.
Michael, how many times did I say
you could go down to Earth?
Actually, you weren't 100% explicit--
One time. I said you could go down there,
save their lives, start the new timeline
and then come back here to observe them.
"One time," is what I said. Uno.
One!
Your Honor, I have to say,
I support you one-hundo percent.
I mean, what Michael did is unbelievable.
Now, granted, I also tricked the doorman
and snuck down to Earth,
but what are we gonna do--
[grunts] Ahh!
Do you realize what you did?
You meddled in human affairs.
That ripples out, man!
Do you know
how much weird stuff has happened
because of your little experiment?
England left Europe.
That Hugh Jackman musical
about P.T. Barnum?
It made, like, $400 million.
Also, the Jacksonville Jaguars
are good now.
Impossible.
I'm serious!
They're gonna make the playoffs.
Blake Bortles is kind of okay, maybe?
I don't know. It's being debated
amongst experts. It's confusing.
But whatever it is, it's yo' fault.
Your experiment with the humans is over.
-Are you gonna kill them?
-No!
But starting now,
there is no more monitoring them.
They're just regular humans that
need to hit the regular point threshold
to see if they make it
into the Good Place.
-Hmm.
-And if they don't...
And right now, the two of you
are going back to the Bad Place.
But they'll retire Michael.
And I'll be marbleized.
Well, maybe, you should have
thought about that
before you intervened in human affairs!
I mean, because of you,
Byron Allen owns the Weather Channel now.
Is that bad?
I don't know, but it's weird, man!
Now, come with me.
Hey. My powers are back online.
This must be everything
I tried to summon on Earth.
-Stop it.
-I don't think I can. I'm like a printer,
when the print queue suddenly starts
processing all the unprinted documents.
Oh, man. Buckle up, folks.
[whispering] Let's go. Right now.
Janet, make it stop!
Janet, stop it!
Janet, this is annoying.
Janet!
Good luck, frog man. Pullin' for ya.
[Judge] Janet, I know you're still there!
[grunting]
They escaped.
Yeah. Thanks, Jeff.