[panting]
Okay.
That was an insane thing for us to do.
Oh! Okay, good news,
I have the Doorman's key,
so no one will be able to come after us.
-Let's just try to--
-[bell ringing]
Your key is ringing.
I have a question for you:
Are you out of your damn mind?
Your Honor,
look at it from my point of view.
I have never been this angry in my life,
which is the age of the universe!
I understand, but saving the souls of
these four humans is more important,
so we're not coming back until we do.
[Judge] Don't you even try
coming back here,
'cause when you walk through that door,
I am gonna be waiting for you.
Sorry, Judge, I think you're breaking up!
That's impossible.
It's a magical key, you dick.
What are you doing?
I can see you.
This is perfect.
We're right near Chidi's office,
and as far as I can tell,
the whole floor is abandoned.
What do they use it for?
Storage?
-No, this is the journalism department.
-Ah!
Bad for the world, good for us.
So, somehow, with none of our powers,
we have to keep the group intact
and monitor their ethical progress.
-So, how do we do that?
-Not sure.
There's no way to track
people's actual point totals.
Only the accountants
have that information.
But I did install cameras and microphones,
so at least we can keep our eye on them.
-Let's get peepin'!
-[exclaims]
[Janet] Oh, no. Not a great start.
Eleanor farted,
and then she blamed it on her chair.
That's gonna cost her
at least a few points.
There's a bolt missing or something.
Before we begin,
Trevor is dropping out of the study.
He sent me an email last night.
"I'm sad to inform you that I am too ugly
and stupid to be in the study,
and I'm going home to my mommy."
That was me.
I wrote that email.
That's too bad, but we press on.
We're on to stage two of the study.
I'm going to teach you
some philosophical principles,
and then we will explore how those ideas
have affected your personal
moral machineries--
-[Eleanor farts]
-Sorry, Eleanor, did you say something?
No, it's my chair.
It's got this weird design.
Your chair smells bad.
I know! See?
Another person who agrees it's the chair.
Great news, everyone! The funding from
the neuroscience department came through!
And you blew it all on cupcakes?
Exactly what I would have done.
Respect.
[Simone] Eleanor?
Uh, I'm good. I try to avoid
pointless group activities.
You know, like office Christmas parties,
or jury duty.
To me, the single most awful sound
in the universe
is that mangled opening note of
your co-workers singing "Happy Birthday."
Cool stance. Counterpoint:
these are delicious free cupcakes.
Get over yourself and eat one.
Fine.
[Simone] You guys, let's take a picture!
Everyone get in, get in, and say...
oh, say "ventromedial pre-frontal cortex!"
-Ventromedial pre-frontal cortex.
-Jaguars rule!
[inaudible]
[Eleanor] Hey, teach? I've been having
so much fun here,
but I didn't plan to stay in Australia
this long, and I'm super broke.
Any idea where I can get a part-time gig?
What kind of work are you looking for?
Well, I'm really good at telemarketing.
I can usually guess how long to microwave
food without looking at the box.
I'd say those are my two main skills.
Okay!
Dang it.
If Eleanor has to get a job,
she'll miss class,
and that'll slow down her progress.
Are you sure we should be doing this?
It kind of feels like cheating.
No, no, no, it's not cheating.
Think of us as a snowplow,
clearing a path for Eleanor,
so she can more easily
drive along the road of improvement.
Ooh, I love that!
You really painted a picture there.
-G'day. How can I help you?
-One scratch-off lottery ticket, please.
Oh, not that one.
Keep going, keep going, keep going.
These tickets were printed
before we got down here.
I know which ones are the winners.
And stop! That's the one!
Good ol' lucky number 186 from the bottom!
Here you go.
Also, that bathroom key that you lost
nine months ago slid under the register.
And the woman that you think is your aunt
is actually your mom. Okay, bye!
You guys, this is nuts!
This morning, I found a lottery ticket
on the ground outside my apartment.
I scratched it off, and I won $18,000!
-[Chidi] Wow!
-[Jason] That's amazing!
Better luck next time.
Yes, sorry, from context, I see
that is actually a large sum of money.
[inaudible]
Jason, you okay there, mate?
No. I have to watch the Jaguar games
alone, on my computer,
at 3:00 in the morning, on Mondays.
It's so annoying.
Everything here is in a...
I don't know how to describe it...
like, a different zone of time.
No, that sounds stupid.
A different clock land.
I'll watch the game with you, Jason!
I enjoy American football.
I actually dated a player once.
But he wasn't my type, so I set him up
with my friend Gisele...
Bündchen.
Yeah, we got it. We always get it.
Awesome! But if you want to watch with me,
you have to learn my Jaguars cheer.
It goes, "Let's go, Jags!
Kick their ass! Yeah!"
Do you think you can learn that
by the weekend?
-I shall do my best.
-[Jason] Nice! See you then!
Why do you want to watch
football with Jason?
I don't, really. But I am, these days,
as you might say in America,
"mad horny."
-Oh! Okay.
-Oh, boy.
Well, no judgements, babe.
He's a straight hottie.
You want to smash Jason, go smash.
Tahani getting together with Jason,
even casually,
could tear this group apart.
We have to nip this in the bud.
Well, it makes me slightly uneasy
to interfere
in the personal life of the man
that I am secretly in love with
and a woman I admire, but if you think
we should, I'm not gonna argue.
Time to break out
the ol' snowplow again, Janet.
Let's find Tahani a loving,
supportive companion.
Great idea.
You know,
this is not as crucial to the mission,
but I'd also love to arrange for them
to get better computers.
Help them work faster.
If I'm going to the mall anyway,
I might as well pick
Jason up some jean shorts,
the kind with the frayed edges, where you
can see the pockets coming out the bottom?
So that he can study better.
Sure.
[indistinct chatter]
Tahani? Is that you?
Larry Hemsworth? My goodness!
That's so funny,
I just got a call from the restaurant
about a jacket I left here,
and now here you are!
[both chuckle]
I can't believe you remember me.
Of course I remember you.
We dated.
I know, I just never expect
anyone to remember me.
Because I'm only 6'4"
and I have one of those forgettable faces.
Well, uh, I'm sure you're busy,
probably don't want to talk to me.
I get it. I wouldn't either,
I'm as dull as a rock.
Ugh! Even that analogy was boring.
I'm sorry, I'm so dull and I'm ugly,
I'm like a rock. [groans]
Stupid Larry! Stop talking about rocks!
No, no, no, Larry, please!
It's lovely to see you.
Sit down. Let's catch up!
How are Chris, and Liam and Luke?
-[Larry sighs]
-Sorry.
No, I won't mention
your brothers again.
As long as you don't mention my sister!
-Oh! [chuckles]
-[Tahani laughs]
[Janet] Mmm-mmm!
Who are you?
Do you work here?
Your name is Montgomery Wycoff.
Your ex-wife Samantha still loves you,
but she's afraid to call.
You must show her your poetry.
Go to her. Go to her!
-Looks like you had a good night!
-I did.
You and Jason, imagine that.
To be fair, I have.
Actually, I was with an ex-boyfriend.
I ran into him unexpectedly
and the reunion was a smashing success.
-It's a pun, you see. We had intercourse.
-Yeah, again, I always get it.
I do feel bad, though.
I completely forgot about watching
the game with Jason.
Homies, guess what?
Yesterday, I got a Facebook invite
to the Australia chapter
of the Jacksonville Jaguars fan club!
Yeah, I think he's over it.
Me and two other dudes just watched
the Jags annihilate the Texans.
It was super fun!
I'm completely wasted.
I gotta go barf one last time,
and then I'll be ready
to learn philosophy!
Duval!
Okay, not perfect,
but the pros outweigh the cons.
Agreed.
[all] Happy birthday, dear Chidi...
You guys, this whole year
has been amazing for all of us.
I mean, literally every aspect
of our lives has improved.
Well, I don't know about every aspect.
SuperBoard, activate!
[automated voice speaking]
Good morning, Professor Anagonye.
I have your lesson plan ready to go.
SuperBoard, some triumphant
announcement music, please.
[fanfare playing]
Last night, Larry Hemsworth proposed to me
and we're moving back to London
to begin planning the wedding!
-Holy smokes!
-[Simone and Jason exclaim]
Janet! Red alert!
All snowplowing has to stop immediately.
So, don't give Blake Beartles to Jason?
How are you even
lugging this thing around?
I'm not sure I could
bench this much weight.
Well, girls in my social class
begin ring-training at a very young age.
Oh, I'm throwing a little engagement party
tonight at my Airbnb.
It's very last minute.
Come as you are.
I guess all these people...
came as they were?
Hello, everyone. I'm so glad you made it.
Holy crap, Tahani,
you found this place on Airbnb?
Oh, no. [chuckles]
I see why you're confused.
I used Heirbnb. "H-E-I-R."
It's an app for heirs and heiresses
where we swap mansions,
private islands, blimp hangars,
that sort of thing.
Anyway, everyone,
I want you to meet Larry Hemsworth.
Oh! The legendary study group.
I'm sorry it's taken me so long
to build up the courage to meet you.
I guess you can see why.
Is he ashamed at having a perfect jawline
and zero percent body fat?
Still can't believe she wants to marry me.
A dumb, old pediatric surgeon
who barely has an eight-pack.
Do you know what you look like?
More importantly, did Miley Cyrus
write the song "Wrecking Ball"
about Chris' brother Liam?
Wonderful.
More questions about my talented brothers.
God forbid there's a single day
when I'm the special one.
Sweetheart, don't go!
You're important, too!
Fixing babies' spines
is just as valuable as acting.
Tahani booked a flight
for tomorrow morning
so this party is our only chance
to talk them out of moving.
Maybe we should just let them
go their separate ways
and hope that they learned enough
to get into the Good Place.
No, we know what'll happen.
If the group splits up, they're screwed.
No, we have to isolate Larry
and convince him
that he needs to stay in Australia.
Time to get into character
as Nathaniel Cookswell, mate!
Caterer to the stars!
Huh...
Maybe no accent?
Fine.
Vegemite canapé?
Might as well. Mummy was right.
I'll always be the chubby one.
Good day, mate.
Nathaniel Cookswell, caterer to the stars.
Is it true you're moving to England?
Yeah. Fly out tomorrow.
Oh, that's a long trip.
Well, you must be a confident man,
uprooting your life like that.
You should stay here in Sydney.
It's such a dynamic, international city
that you've only seen 4.8% of...
probably.
I reckon I know what's going on here.
You aren't real caterers, are you?
[both stutter]
Who do you work for? Australian Inquirer?
TMZ? You just want us to stay here
so you can keep mocking me.
"The hideous shame
of the Hemsworth family."
-[Janet] Oh.
-Tahani sees through all that.
And I can't wait until we move
far away from the likes of you,
and I can finally take her last name.
Hate to say it, but the group
probably needs a new member.
I don't know how
we'll ever replace Tahani.
Do you think Margot Robbie's
into philosophy?
Actually, Tahani's announcement
made us take stock.
You know, Simone and I need time
to analyze the data, apply for grants.
We've kind of hit
a natural stopping point.
Yeah, and the next step would be to repeat
the experiment with new subjects,
you know, compare results.
Wait, what are you saying?
That the study's over? We're splitting up?
No, no, no. We're just taking a break,
for a year or so.
And I'm sure you're all anxious
to get back home.
Yeah, I got a lot of stuff
to get back to in Phoenix. [scoffs]
Like... I have a free punch-card
at my spray tan place.
They'll do my left side for free, so...
No, no, no, no!
The whole group is splintering!
Okay, new emergency plan.
I'll deal with Eleanor.
I know it's risky,
but I don't think she'll recognize me.
And I'll deal with Sweet Cheeks.
I mean, Jason's butt. I mean, Jason.
[sighs]
-Shrimp?
-[Eleanor] Always.
[Michael] So...
how do you know Miss Al-Jamil?
You work with her at the university?
Used to. That study is done-zo.
And I was finally starting
to figure things out,
and now I have to start over
from scratch. Again.
Boy, I know how that goes.
Not wanting something to end.
Feeling like your little team
is the last thing
standing between you and oblivion,
that at any moment
the universe could fold up around you
and squeeze the last breath
from your dying lungs.
You're a caterer, right?
It's a very competitive industry.
The point is, I bet that if the study
means that much to you,
it means a lot to everyone else.
You're all just probably waiting
for someone to say it out loud.
You want some cocktail sauce with that?
[glass tinkling]
I would like to acknowledge the wonderful
group of people who brought me here.
If I hadn't decided
to get out of the spotlight
of my "Get Out of the Spotlight" tour,
and come here and join the Brainy Bunch,
I never would have reconnected with Larry.
[crowd exclaims]
So, to celebrate our group,
I had my favorite pâtissier whip this up!
[chuckles]
Would any of you like to say a few words?
Eleanor!
Yay, Eleanor!
If nobody minds, uh...
I would like to address...
the people on this cake, I suppose.
I get that we all have
meaningful lives outside the study.
Well, Tahani and Chidi do.
Jason and I are straight trash.
Ka-kaw!
But just think about
how much progress we've all made
since that picture was taken.
I know that what we're doing is important
and I'm not ready to stop.
And I don't think you guys are, either.
So, let's all stay here and keep it going.
What do you say?
Eleanor, that was absolutely lovely.
[Chidi] It really was. And I am...
I'm so glad that this study
meant that much to you.
-But, realistically--
-That's cool. I get it.
No, you don't need to say it. I got it.
That's all she wrote. Cool.
-Are you okay? I hope you're not mad.
-No, I'm not mad. I'm actually laughing.
Because this whole study was a hilarious,
stupid, pointless joke,
and now it's over, so let's hit the road.
I don't need you guys.
You don't need me.
And since you don't need me,
I'm just gonna take the me
out of this cake.
-[crowd gasps]
-No, no! Eleanor, please!
Sorry, the deed is done!
Pip pip, too late!
Farewell to you, my liege.
And a jolly good
Saint Ploopington's Day to all of you!
USA! USA! USA!
Eleanor? Is that you?
[Eleanor] No.
Called a cab, like, 20 minutes ago.
It says it's ten kilometers away,
which is... I don't even know how far.
It's a little over six miles.
Is that why you came out here?
To scold me about the metric system?
No, I was about to call a cab myself.
I have an early class tomorrow.
Then I saw my friend hiding behind a plant
and I got concerned.
Then my friend lashed out at me again,
so I'm gonna take off and leave her here
with dirty leaves in her hair.
Wait, wait, wait. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Don't go.
You're a brain scientist.
Can you tell me why I did that in there?
I mostly do clinical research
in neuroscience.
I don't really specialize
in temper tantrums.
Maybe you need a child psychologist...
or a binkie.
That's a solid burn.
I deserved it. I did.
But, please, can you help me?
Why did I do that?
Okay, here's my guess.
As humans evolved, the first big problem
we had to overcome was "me versus us."
Learning to sacrifice a little individual
freedom for the benefit of a group.
You know, like sharing food and resources
so we don't starve or get eaten by tigers,
things like that.
Okay, with you so far.
The next problem to overcome was
"us versus them."
Trying to see other groups
different from ours as equals.
That one we're still struggling with.
That's why we have racism,
and nationalism and...
why fans of Stone Cold Steve Austin
hate fans of The Rock.
No! We hate The Rock
because he went Hollywood
and Stone Cold keeps it real,
so The Rock's fans are the real jabronis.
Point made, keep going.
Well, what's interesting about you is...
I don't think you ever got past
the "me versus us" stage.
I mean, have you ever been part
of a group that you really cared about?
-I was in the Girl Scouts.
-Really?
Technically, I joined under a fake name,
because I wanted to steal
a bunch of cookies.
See? The Brainy Bunch is
basically the first group
that became part of your self identity,
and now that's breaking up,
you're feeling this new kind of loss.
And you're scared of going back
to being alone.
I mean, that's just my guess.
The other possible medical diagnosis
is that you're just a bit of a dick.
[both chuckle]
[Eleanor] Why don't you take my cab?
I think "me" needs to go
apologize to "us." And thank you.
The point is,
I'm not really an "I'm sorry" type girl.
I'm more of a "It's your fault
your car got keyed
in the movie theater parking lot,
because you wouldn't shut up
while watching John Wick" type girl.
But I'm sorry that I freaked out.
Just really gonna miss you guys.
We're gonna miss you, too.
Here's an idea.
What if we all agree to a yearly reunion?
And then that way,
the Brainy Bunch never dies.
Each summer, we could all stay
in one of our respective houses,
mega-yachts, ski chalets, what have you.
We should all meet up in Jacksonville!
My house is right on the water.
It didn't used to be,
but the whole city is a swamp
and it's sinking into the ocean.
Whoo! Strong pitch, bud.
-Next year in Jacksonville!
-Yeah!
We might not want to wait a whole year.
It's sinking really fast.
-We should have a toast.
-[exhales sharply]
Okay, I think I figured out a plan
where they stay in Australia,
and only five random bystanders get hurt.
It's called arson.
Let's go!
Michael, no.
We can't keep meddling forever.
It's time to park the snowplow
and trust that the humans
will make progress on their own.
This isn't like your afterlife
neighborhood, Michael.
You can't just reset things
the moment something doesn't go
according to your plan.
Oh, Janet, you're a genius.
Correct. I know everything.
You just gave me this crazy idea.
It's so crazy, it just might... fail.
It'll probably fail.
But it also might work.
I open the door to the afterlife.
You keep a lookout
while I break into the Judge's chamber
and reset the timeline on Earth.
We do it all over again, but correctly.
We won't wait a year
to get them all together again.
We'll get the study going right away!
But do you even know how to reset
the timeline on Earth?
[sighs] No. I'm assuming that there's
a knob, or a button or, you know...
maybe you unplug it
and then plug it right back in?
I don't... There's gotta be a way!
-Michael, before you do this--
-No! No more waiting.
This is all we have, Janet.
We have Chidi, and Eleanor,
and Tahani and Jason, and that is it.
If we can't get them
enough afterlife points
to get them into the Good Place,
then there's no point in us
even being here. We have to try.
-Okay. Let's do this.
-Yeah, okay.
What the hell is that?
Oh! Hey, guys!
What are you doing down here?