Wow! [exclaims]
Janet, you did it!
You brought us into your void!
If I had a heart, it would be pounding.
-Michael--
-You'd think there'd be side effects,
but I feel great.
How's the hair?
Is it still amazing?
Michael, there may have been
some side effects for the humans.
Huh.
Dude, why are there so many Janets?
And why do I sound like Janet?
You also look like Janet.
Do I? Why? What?
What is happening? [grunts]
Oh, no. Am I wearing a vest?
Oh! Michael, help me!
This is gonna be tricky.
How do we even tell them apart?
Oh! [laughs]
Okay, that one's Jason.
I can't put the humans
back in their own bodies,
so I've done the next best,
but still not that great, thing.
A high-neck sleeveless?
I suppose this outfit will do.
Are you sure?
I mean, wearing a floral print
to an infinite void
at this time of the nothing?
So where are we exactly?
We're not on Earth, right?
That's correct, Chidi-Janet. You're not.
Your real bodies dematerialized
when you entered my void,
and your essences reconstituted themselves
in this form.
Cool, cool. And when you say "void"...
Oh, I mean a subdimension
outside of space and time,
at the nexus of consciousness and matter,
tethered to my essence. Does that help?
It does not help. Makes it way worse.
I just wanna lie down. Where is down?
I found it. It's up here. It's dope!
I have an idea.
[Janet] Sweet! I call sofa.
[Michael] Janet's void has a back door
to the Janet Warehouse
in the Neutral Zone,
which is right near Accounting.
You four will stay here
while actual Janet and I sneak through it
and find the Head Accountant.
But, Michael, why can't we go with you?
Well, you just died, which means
you're the first humans in history
to not immediately go
to the Good or Bad Place,
which, in turn,
makes you interdimensional fugitives.
So, that's neat.
Also, the Judge is probably
still pissed at me,
for, you know, breaking all the rules
and she might take it out on you.
Plus, the Bad Place
is probably hunting for us.
So, literally,
the entire universe is against you.
Okay, but what's a fourth
really good reason?
Jeez. Just trying to lighten the mood.
Tough void.
Now, Janet and I will pose
as Good Place employees,
and sweet talk the Accountant
into showing us his books.
If I'm right, we will find proof
that the Bad Place
is tampering with the points system.
The Accountant will tell us what to do
and this will all be over.
We're almost at the end, guys.
Just stay here
and keep Janet's heads on straight.
[Janet] Bye!
-Is that a Good Janet or a Bad Janet?
-That's a Neutral Janet.
She's sort of the black sheep
of the Janet world.
Or blank sheep, I guess.
Ooh! I can throw shade now. That's cool.
You've arrived at the Accounting office.
All point calculations for actions
taken on Earth are made here.
-End of conversation.
-My name is Michael.
I need to speak with the Head Accountant
on official Good Place business.
I will inform the Head Accountant
of your presence,
and he either will or will not see you
in a certain amount of time.
End of conversation.
Wow!
Good thing your void plan worked out, huh?
[burps]
♪ ...believe in life after love ♪
Mmm.
Having four humans in my void is weird.
-Ah.
-[Janet sighs]
This is nuts. We're in a void
in the body of a white lady--
-Not a lady.
-Not a lady, darling.
But we are white.
Let's all say white people things.
"Billy Joel." "I found it on Etsy."
"There was nowhere to park!"
"Did you refill the Brita?"
I find this void quite calming, actually.
It's like, this time, the Xanax took me.
Oh, I have the worst stomachache.
Dude, relax.
Here, let me see if I can figure this out.
Oh! Wow!
-Eleanor, how'd you do that?
-[Eleanor-Janet] I don't know.
We're Janets now. So, I thought
we'd have some bitchin' Janet powers.
What just happened?
What did you do?
Sorry, I’m just trying
to help Chidi calm--
The structural integrity of this void
is already at risk.
You can't start
randomly conjuring up objects,
or it might shatter the void.
Yes, it might.
It might make everything blow up
and we'll all disappear forever.
So, stop it!
-Everything okay?
-Nope.
Well...
[Neutral Janet] The Head Accountant
has decided to see you.
This will happen now. End of conversation.
Hi.
Heyo! There they are. Good to see you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Neil, Head Accountant.
You must be Janet and Michael.
-Yes.
-[Neil] Can I just say,
I really depreciate you coming.
Uh? Little bit of accounting humor.
-[chuckles]
-Yeah. So, what can I do for you?
Well, I'm concerned about
certain anomalies in the points system.
I'm worried that somehow
the Bad Place has been tampering.
Tampering? No, no.
Quite impossible. Laughable, really.
Janet, can you remind me
to laugh at that later?
Your amusement has been scheduled.
End of conversation.
She's a lot of fun.
Could you just humor us, though?
Show us how the system works.
Ah! Well, I suppose
I could give you a quick tour.
We don't get a lot of visitors. Follow me.
Eleanor, how'd you know
I always wanted a dog like this?
Funny story, it's one of the things
I saw in the alternate timeline
where we were soulmates
on and off for 300 years.
Maybe we should talk about that?
Well, I suppose we can,
but there's not that much to talk about.
The things you saw
weren't part of my life,
so they didn't happen to me.
What the hell are you talking about?
Of course it was you. I saw it.
Well, it was a Chidi, sure,
but it wasn't me Chidi.
This is a classic philosophical question,
the concept of the self,
or who we are.
Philosophically speaking,
there's the Chidi I am,
who lived a certain life,
and there's the Chidi you saw,
your soulmate or whatever,
who had some entirely different life.
Not the same Chidis.
[chuckles] I'm so sorry.
Yeah, no, I get it.
Counterpoint, that's the dumbest thing
you've ever said,
and you do not deserve a puppy!
I'm un-blooping your puppy!
[puppies whining]
-[grunts]
-[puppies barking]
Things are getting cuter
and I want them to get less cute!
So, this is the main feed.
Every action
by every human on Earth is recorded,
and then sent here
to be assigned a point value
based on the absolute moral worth
of that action.
For example, a couple in Ōsaka, Japan,
just decided
to have a destination wedding.
Negative 1,200 points.
And it's a destination theme wedding.
Negative 4,300.
The theme's Lord of the Rings.
They're basically doomed.
Oh! Here's fun. This means that someone
has just done something
which has never been done before.
Richard Moore of Sugar Land, Texas,
hollowed out an eggplant
and filled it with hot sauce and nickels.
And, amazingly,
it's not a weird sex thing.
99% of all new human behaviors
are weird sex things, but not in this--
Oh, no, it is a weird sex thing. Yeah.
Well, then we zip that over
to the relevant departments.
In this case, Anastasia
in the Stuffed Vegetable Department.
We've got Hector over in American Coins,
and my dear buddy, Matt,
in Weird Sex Things.
I'm still waiting on a response
to the request I filed
for immediate suicide.
Request denied. I love Matty.
He's hilarious.
So, they now examine the action,
its use of resources,
the intentions behind it,
its effects on others--
Correct, and you end up with this.
-And here is why tampering is impossible.
-[printer whirring]
Because this score is then double-checked
by three billion other accountants,
all chosen at random,
and if they come to the same conclusion,
which they always do,
it makes this official.
Anyone who does the same action
the same way loses this many points.
When people die,
their biographical history
and final point totals
are sent to the relevant destination.
This batch is going to the Bad Place.
Thank you, Doris.
The system is flawless
-and tampering is quite impossible.
-[Michael] I see.
Could we look at one specific file,
though, just to make sure?
Oh. Who do you wanna see?
Genghis Khan? Marie-Antoinette?
Walt Disney's got some freaky stuff
in his file.
Doug Forcett.
I don't get this, man.
Why wouldn't you want to know
what our life was like?
You're not even a little bit curious
what it was like to hit this?
I don't mean this-this.
Although, frankly,
I would also hit this-this.
I don't want to see those memories
because, philosophically speaking,
they're none of my business.
They happened to someone else.
Let me explain.
Take a seat.
"Conceptions of the Self."
Let's start with John Locke,
who believed that personal identity
was based on having
a continued consciousness.
Essentially, memory.
Memories are links in a chain
that together form a single self.
If I can't remember what happened,
because it happened to a Chidi
from another timeline,
it's not a unified me.
Just because
you don't remember doing something
doesn't mean you didn't do it.
I have no idea how it happened,
but there is definitely a tattoo
on my butt that says "Jasom."
That brings us to Derek Parfit.
It does?
Parfit said, "Even if I have memories
from an earlier time,
that doesn't necessarily mean it was me."
After all, if my brain was split in two
and each half
was put in a different person,
which one is me?
All I know is
that other Chidi doesn't exist anymore,
and this one does,
so this must be the real Chidi.
And all I know is that you're just
barfing Wikipedia all over everyone
to avoid talking about your feelings.
Let's talk about David Hume.
[Neil] Hmm.
Here we go, the Book of Dougs.
Let's have us a look.
Doug Forbush... Forcap... Doug L. Forcett.
Hey, no peeking. Accountants only.
Can you just tell me his total so far?
Looks like he's at 520,000 points.
-Well done, Doug.
-So, that's good?
Oh, it's excellent.
Wait. He's 68 years old?
That's terrible. He's screwed.
[Michael] I knew it!
Doug has spent his entire life
being nothing but good.
He once found a dollar on the ground
and he sent it to the Canadian government
to help pay down their national debt,
and he isn't even close to getting in?
How can that be?
Look, mate, the points are indisputable.
They have been since the beginning.
"Og gives his rock to Grog."
First ever act of human altruism.
Og earned 10,000 points that day.
'Course, then Grog used that rock
to beat Og's brains in
and lost a million points.
Point is, the math
is cold, objective and airtight.
And unless you can prove otherwise,
I don't know how I can help you.
I just got 700 new Weird Sex Thing files
in the last one second.
Oh, yeah, Burning Man just started.
Buckle up, Matty!
It's going to be a long week.
So, in essence, Hume thought
that we don't truly have a self.
We're just a bundle
of our ever-changing impressions.
Just admit it, man.
You're embarrassed you fell in love
with an Arizona trash bag.
Eleanor, it's not personal.
Someone fell in love with you.
It's just not me.
I told you not to conjure anything!
Sorry. I just swapped the living room
for a classroom.
Not you, him.
-Jason, what is wrong with you?
-Sorry, Janet.
I didn't mean to conjure Pillboi.
I was just thinking
about how much fun we used to have,
hanging out in his broken hot tub
and then he showed up.
Yeah, I was just chillin' being nothing.
Then, all of a sudden, I was.
-[Jason-Janet exclaims]
-[Pillboi chuckles]
Goodbye, Pillboi.
Ah, dip, I'm not again...
Oh...
You need to hurry.
My molecular essence is fragmenting
and it's giving me the worst headache.
Okay, here's a question,
if Doug Forcett's not getting in, who is?
Let's look at one more file.
Someone who's gotten into the Good Place
this year.
All right. Why don't we look at...
No one. No one got in.
-No one's gotten in for a year?
-Correct.
How about the last three years?
All right. Uh... [scatting]
Ah... No one.
When was the last time someone got in?
[Neil] The last time someone got enough
points to get into the Good Place was...
521 years ago.
Michael... Um...
Yo, homie.
You and Eleanor were fighting before
and I couldn't help but overhear.
Hey, if we hear with our ears,
why is it called "butt overhearing"?
Bro, if you don't like her,
you should just tell her.
[sighs] It's not about whether
I like Eleanor.
I got into philosophy
to try to make sense of a world
that almost never makes sense,
and that was before I learned that I died,
and then un-died and then re-died.
I just can't take one more thing.
It's too much.
I'm gonna tell you a story.
Back in Jacksonville,
there was this guy in my 80-person
dance crew named Stank Toby--
Hang on. It was a 60-person dance crew.
Um...
Oh, dip! What are numbers?
You're not Jason-Janet.
You're Eleanor-Janet pretending
to be Jason-Janet.
That is so wrong and so confusing!
What was I supposed to do, man?
You wouldn't talk to me.
This seemed like the only option.
[imitates Eleanor] Hi, Chidi, I'm Eleanor.
I'm Arizona shrimp horny!
That's not what I sound like, Jason.
Get out of here!
Oh, dip.
Look, you know what? Just forget it!
What am I even doing?
I'm chasing a dude who isn't into me.
I'm making myself vulnerable
for no reason.
I don't even know who I am anymore.
Uh-oh.
This is new.
I'm so annoyed at myself!
[scoffs] Stupid Eleanor! Stupid!
-This whole thing sucks, you know?
-Eleanor, you're not--
The one thing I never wanted to do, ever,
for any reason,
was to follow some guy around
like a lame puppy dog.
I mean, look at me.
I don't need to do that.
I can get any guy I want.
Eleanor, just... Hang on.
What, dude? What? What do you want?
What is going on?
Okay, well, this is bad.
Why are you staring at me?
Do I have a zit on my nose or something?
Your sense of self is crumbling
and it's taking the void down with it.
Great. So, I don't feel like myself for
two seconds and it breaks the universe?
How come nothing went wrong
when Chidi freaked out about his identity
for three hours?
Because freaking out about everything
is my identity. Not to brag.
I need you to hold it together.
Try to do something Eleanor-y.
Laugh at someone who falls down
or show up at an event underdressed
and get mad at everyone else somehow.
I'll be right back.
[distant explosion]
I know I asked you this before, but--
No, darling. This is not
where the Mac and PC guys live.
Whoa! Check out this dope flat screen.
It's air-mounted!
Do you see this, Tahani?
[Tahani-Janet] This must be where
Janet stores all her information.
This screen can literally show us anything
that has ever happened.
Cartoons! Cartoons!
I think it's broken.
TV, play cartoons for Jason.
Oh, my. Janet has a crush on you.
I'm sorry. It's not just a crush.
I think, in one of the reboots,
you and Janet were married.
Whoa! Married?
Oh...
This flat screen
must have been a wedding present.
It's all starting to make sense now.
Well, I've gotta run.
We're having a little thing
in the break room for Marisol's birthday.
She's turning 39 million again.
So, if there's nothing else...
"If there's nothing else"?
Neil, be logical.
Not one Good Place resident
in over 500 years?
Not Jonas Salk? Not Harriet Tubman?
Not one single Golden Girl?
The Bad Place has hacked your system!
No, it hasn't. How dare you?
Frankly, I'm beginning to resent
your tone, sir. If you've got a problem,
then go to the Good Place
and take it up with the Committee.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to get to the break room,
because there's cake over there,
and if I don't move quickly,
Erika will get the last corner piece!
Good day, sir.
[Michael] Oh, no, no,
this can't be happening.
No, he was supposed to tell us what to do.
If he's not gonna fix this, who is?
You, Michael.
It has to be you.
We keep wandering
around these different realms,
expecting someone else to have the answer,
but no one ever does.
You're the guy, Michael.
You're the only one who can fix
whatever's wrong with the afterlife.
But before we get into that,
Eleanor's identity is shattering
inside my void, and I might blow up,
so I'm gonna need you to grab a paper clip
and marbleize me, like, yesterday.
-What's gonna happen to the humans?
-[Janet] No idea,
but I can't take them out of my void
in the middle of this office.
And if we do nothing, everyone is gone-zo.
Marbleize me, get us somewhere safe
and bring me back.
Right. Paper clip! I need a paper clip!
Hey, Matt! Do you have a paper clip?
What are you gonna use it for?
-Chidi, I'm scared.
-I know.
What am I supposed to be doing right now?
I don't remember.
I'm having a hard time remembering.
Right. Memories.
You need to remember who you are.
You're Eleanor Shellstrop
from Phoenix, Arizona.
Your favorite meal is shrimp scampi.
You listed your emergency contact
as Britney Spears
as a long-shot way of meeting her,
and your favorite movie is that clip
of John Travolta saying "Adele Dazeem."
You flew halfway around the world
because you wanted to be a better person,
and it was very brave.
You're sharp and you're strong.
You make fun of me a lot.
You once called me a human snooze button,
but you also showed up in my classroom
when I was drowning
in despair and canned chili,
and you basically saved my life.
You have very high self-esteem,
and a very low tolerance
for men who wear sandals,
and your worst nightmare
is someone saying
something nice about you to your face,
but too bad, because I need to say it,
because you deserve it.
-Because... Because...
-Chidi...
-[Chidi sighs]
-[Eleanor panting]
[chuckles]
Nice work, bud.
Did you mean everything you said
or did you just say it
because the world was ending?
I really wanna play this cool,
but I'm afraid that I'm gonna ruin it
if I try to be sexy.
I already ruined it. Um...
Saying the word "sexy" is not sexy.
-Wait!
-Oh! Jeez.
I'm okay.
-Are you sure?
-Yes. I'm okay.
Wait. Uh-oh. Ooh.
What?
They're not Janets anymore.
They're them and they're not sitting well.
[exhales] Incoming.
They're all here, and they're safe...
-[all chuckling]
-[alarm blaring]
...from the old scary thing.
Now, there's a new scary thing.
Hi, guys. I'm Neil. Welcome to Accounting.
Now, it does seem that four of you
are interdimensional fugitives,
so I did go ahead and hit the alarm.
Sorry about that.
But there is some good news.
There's some cake left.
Yes!
Michael, what are we going to do?
Guys, I'm so sorry.
The Accountant was no help.
Rude.
No one's gotten into the Good Place
in 500 years.
We have no plan.
No one's coming to save us.
So...
I'm gonna do it.
-Follow me!
-[all exclaim]
The corner piece! No!
You can't take the Book of Dougs.
Accountants only!
I need one of you to volunteer
to do something outrageously insane
that will either make you cease to exist
or be really fun.
That's most of the things I've tried!
That's my guy. Come here. Get in the tube!
Oh, hell, yeah. I love getting in stuff!
-[Michael sighs]
-[alarm continues to beep]
[Tahani exclaims]
No way to know what happened to him.
So, come on, let's go.
Everyone else, come up. Here you go.
-[all shouting indistinctly]
-[thudding]
That was awesome! That was awesome!
I want to go again.
[all panting]
Where are we?
We're in the Good Place.
No offense, dude,
but you have told us a lot of lies
in the last 300 years,
so seriously, where the fork are we?
Fork. Shirt. Ashhole.
[gasps]
Holy forking shirtballs.
We're in the Good Place.