Oh, Janet, you disappoint me.
I expected more of a fight from you.
Yet here you are,
all alone in the Bad Place,
rendered powerless
by a measly magnet jail.
[laughs boisterously]
It's okay, I guess.
What is the issue now, hmm?
That's not how Michael laughs.
It's more of a delighted giggle.
[Shawn] She's right.
You need to nail his subtleties
and mannerisms
for this to properly work as torture.
[sighs]
My problem with the role
is that I haven't fully figured out
Michael's motivation yet.
Like, I'm inside Michael,
but I need to be "inside" Michael.
Hmm. You know, it actually
feels more like torture
when you discuss your "acting process."
You don't get it.
If you really wanna know
Michael's motivation,
it's the same as the rest of my friends:
Loyalty, empathy and love.
-Ew.
-And that's why they will prevail.
I hate to break it to you, hon.
They're not gonna prevail.
No one's coming to save you.
[laughs maliciously]
-Oof. Getting colder.
-I know!
I could feel it. You know, it was wrong.
I'm just... I'm in my head now.
[groans]
[Jason] Hey, Mikey, I have
a question about our plan to save Janet.
Is there it yet?
I do have a plan, yes.
But to be honest,
I have no idea if it will work.
Maybe Glenn can help.
Yo, Glenn!
How should we rescue Janet?
[bubbling]
He doesn't know.
Listen, Jason, old friend.
I already gave Eleanor and Tahani
all their afterlife memories back.
I haven't restored yours...
for obvious reasons.
But I think to maximize
our chances of survival,
it's time that you remember
everything we've been through.
Prepare yourself, this might be intense.
Oh... dip!
[Jason panting]
-Do you remember everything?
-Yes.
Last time I was in the Bad Place,
I threw a Molotov cocktail.
That was sick.
I was afraid that you'd watch
300 years of memories
and that would be your takeaway.
Buddy, I did that
to help you know what not to do.
Impulse control is critical.
Fight the urge to blow stuff up,
even if you feel like we're in a jam.
Got it?
I mean, that's very lame,
but, yeah, I understand.
Wait, can I have
all my memories back again?
I forgot most of them.
[theme music playing]
Welcome, everyone!
Janet will be unavailable for a bit.
She's undergoing some
routine system maintenance.
Oh, I know what that means.
Eye lift, maybe an ear tuck.
[Chidi] Mmm. Mmm! Mmm.
When we don't have Janet,
we like to refresh your memories
of your old lives,
when you did things for yourselves.
We call it Earth Day!
And, yes, we know that's a thing on Earth,
[scoffs] but what are they
gonna do, sue us?
[crowd laughs]
So, get ready for
some fun, lo-fi activities.
-This group over here is gonna knit.
-[gasps]
You folks are gonna do
your favorite activity, gardening.
[cheers]
Oh, man, we better get
something better than that.
And you five are going
to a gorgeous, remote lake house.
Swimming, waterskiing, the works.
[laughs]
Suck it, gardeners.
Why do I feel like
that's not the first time
he's screamed those words?
Ugh. Get me down from here,
you tiny butthole.
Ow!
Thank you for keeping me safe
from my sexy, bad-girl sister-aunt.
Ew.
I know that I've caused you a lot
of trouble in the past... Classic Derek.
But from now on, I'm here to help.
I'd feel a lot more confident
if you weren't holding a champagne glass
full of Scrabble letters,
but you're all we got.
You can keep
the neighborhood running, right?
Well, I wasn't technically
designed for this,
[chuckles] but to be fair,
I wasn't designed for anything.
Okay, we're gonna get the humans
far away from the center of town
to help lighten your load.
That would be really great.
-Okay.
All right, babe, it's go time. You ready?
Absolutely.
I feel very confident with you in charge.
In the words of my godfather,
acting in what can only be described
in hindsight
as his most problematic role...
"You the man now, dawg."
As always, thank you for finding
the quickest possible way to say things.
Now, head off to the lake house,
and do your fabulous Tahani hostess thing!
Actually, uh, now that you bring it up,
Michael and Jason are rescuing Janet
and you're running things here.
Even Derek has an important job.
Ah.
I'd like to be more useful.
What is it that you Americans say? Uh...
"Insert me, coach man!"
"Put me in, coach."
Babe, we need these humans
to stay happy and occupied.
All right? So just
pump 'em full of champagne,
and those tiny little sandwiches
and keep 'em dazzled.
[chuckles] Of course.
Though I'd never serve
finger sandwiches at a lake house.
I mean, what am I, Welsh? [chuckles]
Are you? I don't know.
No, right?
Okay. We have to move quietly.
We can't be seen by anyone
until we get to Shawn.
It's the only way to rescue Janet.
Uh, Michael?
I'm scared.
Me, too, bud.
I mean, what if all this time apart
has changed me and Janet's relationship?
What if that special connection is gone?
Yeah.
I mean, for me, it's scary that
we're standing in the birthplace of evil,
surrounded by billions of demons
who wanna destroy us.
Hmm.
I guess we both have things
we're scared about.
[Tahani] Hello, all.
I took the liberty of preparing
a few simple snacks.
Ooh! This place is nice.
Did anyone else see that movie
The Lake House with Keanu and Sandy B?
Ugh, I love a movie with gentle magic.
Gimme a time-traveling mailbox,
or a mother-daughter body switch,
or, like, Sarah Michelle Gellar as a chef
and her food tastes amazing
because she cries in it. [chuckles]
I should have been a screenwriter.
Yeah. This'll do, I guess.
I got dibs on the master bedroom.
-Um, Simone? Where's Chidi?
-He decided to just stay at home and read.
He said swimming in lakes scares him.
To be fair, most things scare him.
Well, never fear.
You all stay and enjoy
the full-sized sandwiches.
I shall go and fetch Chidi. [chuckles]
Tahani is on the job.
Perv 'stache, four eyes...
bee monster.
Whoa!
Is that you?
[Michael] Technically, yes.
But it's a version of me
I no longer recognize.
Behind that handsome smile
was so much cruelty,
so much pain inflicted on so many,
with such glee.
Shameful.
What echoes of this former self
await me here?
[Jason] I feel you.
It was always hard for me to go back
to my old high school.
So many memories.
Also, the junkyard machine
crushed it into tiny cubes.
If we get out of here alive,
remind me to re-erase your teen years.
Come on, guys. Hurry back.
[exhales heavily]
Oh. Hey, Wanda. Everything okay?
Barg-de-barg-de-barg-de-barg.
Come again?
-Oh.
-Barg-de-barg-de-barg-de-barg.
-Derek?
-Oh! Hey!
So, uh... things are... not going well.
-Hi there!
-Hi!
[Eleanor] You said you could handle this.
Yeah, well, it turns out
being a single father to 300 kids
is not that easy, Eleanor.
Okay, well, the four humans
are still at the lake house,
so we can figure this out.
-What are you doing here?
-I came to get Chidi.
He decided to stay home.
Chidi's up there? Right now?
Oh, Chidi, there you are.
Hi. Sorry, I should've told you.
I decided to just stay home and read.
Swimming in lakes scares me,
and so does waterskiing--
We know all that, Chidi.
We never expected you
to meet the group at the lake house.
We had a special solo activity
planned for you.
-Really? What is it?
-Mmm-hmm.
We have hidden several clues
in this apartment to a puzzle.
Ooh!
-[chuckles]
-I love puzzles.
They're so much fun,
but they're also like homework. Win-win.
Well, this one's a doozy
because when you solve it,
you get the answer
to the truth about the universe.
[chuckles]
Spoiler alert... I guess.
Hey, Tahani, you've been so helpful,
but everyone's back at the lake house
with no party hostess,
which is obviously less than ideal.
So, go on, get.
-[chuckles] Of course.
-Yeah.
-Good luck, Chidi.
-Okay.
So, what's my first clue?
You've already gotten it.
Ooh!
[indistinct chatter]
[Shawn] All right, idiots.
This is hour 52 of the 4,000-hour
presentation on the future of torture.
-He's gonna be on stage for 4,000 hours?
-[shushes]
Here's what I think.
We should throw a Molotov--
-Jason.
-What? I didn't say cocktail.
I could've meant Molotov anything.
You don't know.
[Michael] Just trust me. I have a plan.
Humans are worse than ever.
We have to innovate.
Sure, poking sticks work great,
but should those sticks
be sharper or hotter?
Should they counter-intuitively
be less hot?
Let's begin with
slide number one of 7,000.
[clapping]
Nice speech... not!
What's up, dingus?
Oh, no. Oh, that's not good.
Oh, what are you guys... Oh, no.
Don't do that. That's not Derek.
-Derek.
-[Derek groans]
I'm going back to the lake house
to entertain,
because, apparently,
that's all I'm good for.
-Okay.
-I'm gonna need some party supplies.
Cocktail napkins with
a cute, lake-related slogan.
Maybe they could say
"better lake than never."
Oh, sorry, I've just got
nothing left in the tank.
Derek, when you get rebooted,
you become more advanced right?
Yeah.
Well, perhaps then you'd be more capable
of controlling the neighborhood.
Hey, yeah, yeah.
You said you wanted to make this up to us.
Well, now is your chance.
-Yes.
Derek.
What are you doing here, Vicky?
You're early.
And do you ever take that suit off?
It smells terrible.
It does?
No need to be alarmed.
I know this might look like Michael,
the traitorous slam-pig.
However, this is actually
our very own Vicky,
wearing the latest in demon technology:
A custom-made, look-alike skinsuit!
-Spin around for us, would ya, hon?
-[exclaims]
As you are all aware, our current system
suffers from diminishing returns.
Sure, the first time someone gets
butthole spiders, he's miserable.
But soon, the humans get used to it,
and worse, the spiders get bored.
These personalized skinsuits represent
the dawn of a new era:
Torture 2.0.
-[Michael] Oh! [laughs]
-[crowd cheers]
And speaking of which, I figured Demon Con
would be the best place to surprise you
with my greatest invention.
Come on out... Jason.
[crowd gasps]
[crowd cheers]
I had the boys down in R&amp;D
make a Jason suit.
Thought it'd be a fun, new way
to torture Janet.
-Come on. Come on. Here you go.
-I didn't okay this.
I know, but, hey, I'm Vicky!
I'm a total munch.
That you are. Good point.
Hmm. Not bad.
They went a little overboard
on the cheekbones, but still.
Wait, who's in there?
-Glenn.
-Makes sense.
Get an idiot to play an idiot.
I was beginning to wonder
where you were, Glenn.
I'm right here... in Jason.
-Definitely not a big bucket of goo.
-[Michael clears throat] Okay.
Say, boss, what do you say we put
these innovative suits of yours to work?
We'll go torture Good Janet
and let you know how it goes.
-Which way is it again?
-Wait.
I have a better idea.
I say we torture Good Janet,
right here, right now, live on stage.
-Rufus, go get the Good Janet.
-[crowd cheers]
[whispering] This part
of your plan seems risky.
This was not part of my plan.
Oh. Thank God,
I thought you had a bad plan!
Okay, it's easy. Just hit the button.
You've seen Mindy do it a million times.
Yeah, here we go.
[sobbing] No, no, no, don't kill me, me.
Don't do it.
[groans] Huh.
Now, why is that so hard? I kinda...
You know what? I see what I gotta do.
Just kinda look at this...
[screaming] Derek!
Excellent.
-[Eleanor] Dude, what were you thinking?
-[Tahani] I just wanted to be useful.
All I ever get to do here
is throw parties,
which is all I ever got to do
back on Earth
and now I've ruined everything.
No, you gave us a way out.
So, I fixed everything.
No, you've made things difficult
in a new way, but I can make it work.
But the important thing is
I did something.
-Be quiet and follow my lead.
-Yes, ma'am.
[Eleanor] Chidi? Come on out, bud.
Okay. Am I close?
No, there's 4,000 clues in here.
You found five.
I'm just gonna skip to the end.
This puzzle was going to take you
on adventures all over the neighborhood.
Horseback riding,
hot air ballooning and...
I asked Tahani to be involved because
she did all of those things on Earth.
You've been in paradise for a month,
and you're still so reluctant
to try new activities.
Yeah, I know, I'm just not
a new-experience kind of guy.
I mean, my comfort zone
is basically... that chair.
And, honestly,
the arms are a little sharp.
I want you to believe
that you're safe here.
That you can trust me.
Do you trust me, Chidi?
Yes. I really do.
Then come with me.
These personalized skinsuits
are a true game-changer.
Imagine being able to torment a human
not as yourself,
but as their wife, or ex-wife,
or just some mouthy broad.
They are so convincing,
they even work on a Good Janet!
[Janet grunts] Jeez!
Ugh. Great, more Vicky.
Hey, your Michael impression stinks
almost as much as your suit. [scoffs]
-Why does everyone keep saying that?
-Pfft. Oof.
Welcome, Janet.
We have a special guest for you today.
[sighs]
Hi, Janet. It's me, Jason.
Your boyfriend.
I really miss you.
I know we were in a fight before,
but I hope you've forgiven me because...
I love you... girl.
Not a girl.
-Well, Janet?
-Yeah.
How's that make you feel?
Terrible. [fake crying]
[Michael chuckles]
Adequate work, Glenn.
-Rufus, take the Janet back to her cell.
-[Janet] No, no, no.
No, please, uh, let us
take Janet back ourselves.
I wanna get a little extra torture time in
on the way there.
I don't see why not.
[Vicky as Michael] Hello, dummies.
-It's me, Michael.
-[crowd gasps]
I'm just kidding.
It's me, Vicky, in a Michael suit.
[chuckles]
What's going on here?
I was never told that I had an understudy.
[Eleanor] There you go, buddy.
You're doing great.
Where are we going?
Um... Somewhere fun. Just follow my voice.
Ooh!
This is, uh... kinda fun.
I'm very scared, but also... I like it?
-Hi, there.
-Hi, whoever you are.
Don't mind us.
We're just doing a trust thing.
Hi, there.
What was that sound?
A unicorn died.
-What?
-No.
[stammering] Not a unicorn, my mistake.
Just a regular horse
that someone stabbed in the head.
What?
[Eleanor grunts]
What in the name of Kevin Spacey's
self-made Christmas Eve video message
to try to get back on
House of Cards is going on here?
-[whispering] Mike.
-[Shawn] Who are you?
[Vicky as Michael] Who am I?
-You had this the whole time?
Yeah. I wanted to explode
a bunch of demons,
but you told me I should wait, so I did.
Vicky, why did you build
a second Michael suit?
He didn't. No, I mean, I didn't.
[stammers] Oh. Look...
[crowd gasps and exclaims]
It can't be.
Yes, it's true.
It's me, the real Michael.
We know all about your plot
to sabotage our experiment.
We know you brought Chris in
to pretend to be Linda
to distract us
while you planted a Bad Janet
to pretend to be a Good Janet.
No, stop clapping. This is real.
Someone capture them.
Rufus, I'm warning you.
I know we go way back.
We used to be roommates.
But if you take another step,
I will use this demon exploder on you.
A "demon exploder"? Come on, man.
At least try to make
that sound convincing.
[crowd gasps]
Wow.
Touché.
I used to be just like all of you.
I sat right where you're sitting,
at more than 10,000 Demon Cons,
and I believed that we committed torture
as a part of the moral balance
of the universe.
But I've learned that's wrong.
Humans are capable of self-improvement,
and so are we.
And down deep,
Shawn knows this is true, too.
I beg you, open your eyes to the truth.
[slow clapping]
Bravo, Michael.
What a monologue... not!
[crowd laughs]
I'm not scared of you.
Because I've gone there, Michael.
I've become you.
You may act like you've changed,
but deep down, you're still a demon.
Vile, ugly, capable of so much darkness.
And now...
you're home.
[crowd gasps]
Oh, come on!
-[Michael] Let's go. Come on.
-Let's go.
[Shawn] No, you morons. Stop
applauding them. They're getting away.
I swear, the production value at Demon Con
gets better every year.
Man, look at this house.
And that beautiful lake.
I can't believe I almost missed all this.
Is this the answer
to the truth about the universe?
-Well--
-Uh... Part of it.
Oh!
The puzzle continues.
Hey, you decided to come after all.
I did.
Thanks to Eleanor and Tahani.
[Simone] Aw! You two are the best.
Well, that was insane.
But we got through it... together.
No, we didn't.
You got through it.
I almost ruined it a hundred times.
From now on, I'm just gonna
stick to throwing parties,
because it's the only thing I'm good at.
[scoffs and fake sobs]
-Hey.
-What?
When I said "throw a party,"
I didn't mean a pity party.
This isn't a pity party.
I'm genuinely sad.
The only thing I can do
is throw pointless parties.
You run the entire neighborhood.
You're so capable.
I have seen you get stuck
in any manner of crazy situation,
and you always figure a way out.
Yeah, man, because I've had to
scrape and claw my way through life,
and you grew up in a castle full of
diamond lamps and golden pillowcases.
You never learned
how to think on your feet.
Look, if the roles were reversed,
and I had to throw a fancy party
to save all of humanity,
I promise we'd be screwed,
because I wouldn't know what salad fork
to put next to the... whatever spoon.
The whatever spoon is really only used
for certain festive jellies.
See?
Babe, the dodos in that house
are literally the four most important
human beings in the universe.
I wanted you to take care of them
because I trust you.
Plus, your parties aren't pointless.
They're opportunities for them
to bond and form friendships.
You know, the thing we need them to do
so we're not all tortured forever?
You're right.
And thank you.
But if we ever get through this,
I want to learn
how to do something meaningful.
A real skill.
Something helpful and fulfilling.
Okay, man, if we survive this,
I promise I will support you while you...
-learn to weld or whatever, deal?
-[chuckles]
Deal.
[fires]
That oughta stop them from following us.
So smart.
Nice to have you back, Janet.
That must have been hard for you...
to go back there.
It was.
I don't like thinking about
who I used to be.
[Jason] Listen, Michael,
it's okay to feel or plead guilty
about bad things you used to do,
but you don't have to feel shame
about who you were,
because you're not a demon anymore.
You're just like a nice, weird,
happy old dude.
Huh. [chuckles]
Thanks for rescuing me.
I missed you so much.
I missed you, too.
Bad Janet was so mean to me.
She told me so many lies.
She said the Jags cut Blake Bortles.
Can you believe that?
Oh, no.
Jason, that wasn't a lie.
Blake Bortles was cut by the Jaguars.
What? How? Why?
Who's their QB now?
A man named Nick Foles.
Nick Foles? Are you kidding me?
He won a Super Bowl!
We're gonna be unstoppable!
Foles!
-Foles! [chuckles]
-Foles!
[Janet] Oh, no.
Nick Foles just broke his clavicle.
[Jason] No!