[whooshing]
[clicking]
Well, that's just... that's uncomfortable.
[chuckles]
Oh, hey, guys. What's up?
"What's up?"
Tell us what happened.
Did we win? Did we lose?
Is humanity saved forever?
And did you find my Nintendo?
I can't find it any... Whoop!
Never mind. I'm holding it.
Sorry. I can't reveal the results
of the experiment
until we get to the Judge's chambers.
[Eleanor] Okay. Where is everyone?
Where's Simone, and John and Brent,
and actually I don't care about
any of those doofs. Where's Chidi?
Oh, he's on the toilet.
Sorry, that's not enough information.
The test subjects are frozen in stasis,
so I put them in the bathroom
and I placed Chidi on the toilet.
The best seat.
Let's wake him up.
You know, so I can, like,
be reunited with the man I love?
Snappy, snappy, memory fixxy?
The Judge says no one gets unfrozen
until she's ruled on the case.
Oh, uh, humans have to stay here.
You can't see the numbers.
Hang on. I worked my ash off
running this neighborhood for a full year,
and I'm not even allowed
to hear how we did?
Yes.
And here's a bottle of tequila.
Okay, let us know how it goes.
Regardless of what the Judge rules,
this feels like some sort of goodbye.
Even if we succeeded, there's
no guarantee she'll keep us together.
She might just snap her fingers
and send us flying
into different dimensions.
How was that? Did I cheer everyone up?
Oh, man, are we gonna die again?
We've died so many times.
We've probably had, like,
15 funerals by now.
It's getting annoying.
If it would cheer you up, I could tell you
what happened at your original funerals.
Tahani, Moby spoke first.
He claimed that--
Please stop. I don't want to hear it.
What about mine?
Your friends didn't say things about you,
so much as they graffitied
a Red Lobster about you.
Yeah, in Jacksonville,
that's the first stage of grief.
In Arizona, you can either have
a regular funeral,
or they can put your body out
on a shooting range,
and you get a $200 state tax credit.
Hang on. This is how we take our minds
off the Judge's ruling.
Let's throw ourselves the funeral
to end all funerals.
[Jason] Awesome!
And you know what they say in Florida,
"If you don't like this funeral,
just wait a minute."
[portal zapping]
Ugh, the Judge's chambers?
I hate this place.
What's the Wi-Fi password?
There is no service.
Shawn.
-Michael.
-Bounces off me and sticks to you.
Wait, no, I messed that up.
First, say something mean to me,
really cruel, something that just guts me.
[chuckling]
You're totally going to be glue.
So, it's come to this.
We have finally arrived at the end of your
pathetic attempt to prove that humans
are more than just mobile turd factories.
And you are going to fail, again,
because that is what you do.
You're a choker, Michael.
And you're about to choke
for the last time.
Except for the eternity
you're going to spend in the Bad Place,
being choked by me,
who will be doing the choking.
Well, you're glue.
-Wow!
-[Paula gasps]
-[Paula] Beautiful!
-[Chuck] Look at this place!
-[man] Amazing!
-[Meg gasps]
The floor!
Hello, Good Place Committee.
Thank you for coming.
No, thank you, Michael.
You did an incredible job,
maybe the best job that anyone's ever done
-at any task.
-Mmm.
But you don't know how we did.
We might not know how you did,
but we know you did great.
And, Shawn, before we even
find out what happened,
we want you to know we're willing
to give up all of our leverage,
-compromise and meet you halfway.
-Mmm-hmm, mmm-hmm.
I met your mom halfway last night.
-[all laughing]
-So colorful!
[Eleanor] We are here to celebrate
the afterlife of Tahani Al-Jamil,
in the place she felt most comfortable,
the cabin of
a Gulfstream G650 private jet.
Tahani was super nice,
and she deserved for people
to be nicer to her than they were.
The only sad thing is that she never
got over her speech impediment.
Tahani improved so much
over her many lives,
but she also helped me improve.
She taught me lots of stuff,
like "Bras shouldn't be painful,"
and, "You don't buy bras at Home Depot,"
and "They don't sell bras at Home Depot.
What the hell are you wearing?"
For the record, it was a men's back
support harness, and it worked in a pinch.
She was the best friend I ever had...
and I loved her.
Thank you so much. That was wonderful.
I wish Chidi was here.
It sucks that he's too dead
for these heaven funerals.
Can someone grab his arm?
My hands are kind of full with his butt.
[groans] How'd he get so jacked?
When he was 14, someone told him
that exercise alleviated anxiety.
He started doing push-ups
and basically never stopped.
[all grunting]
All right, everyone, let's get this done.
This is the single most important case
that has ever appeared in my court,
and the results will have ramifications
for eternity.
Before we begin,
I'm going to need you all to sign this.
[clicks tongue]
"A petition to bring back Ally McBeal"?
Well, yeah. I mean,
everything else is getting rebooted.
Get a young hottie in there,
like a Zendaya type?
Is it Zenday-ah or Zend-iyah?
Zenday-ah. Or, I don't...
I mean, who wouldn't watch that?
Am I right? Anyone?
Oh, fine.
[gavel bangs]
Take it away, Matt.
Okay, the moment
we've all been waiting for.
The test results that dictate
the future of humanity.
Here we go.
-In 30, 29...
-Ahem.
...two, one, voilà!
[musical tones playing]
I thought this would be fun.
Had a lot of time alone in there.
Bam!
Simone got 12% better
than she was on Earth.
Bam! Chidi got 26% better.
Bam! John got 44% better.
[comical music plays on machine]
[sighs] Shoot.
Shouldn't have committed so hard
to this "bam" thing.
Funeral!
Jason, at the risk of getting an answer
that might thoroughly depress me,
what made you choose this setting?
There's a Jacksonville tradition of having
your funeral where you were born.
I got born in the deep end of a pool,
right after my mom did a cannonball.
Well, I knew the risks.
You never really talk about your mom.
Yeah, she died when I was pretty young.
I lost her to the Big C.
That's what we called the crocodile
that lived by my house.
I'm just playing, it was cancer.
Watch me do a handstand.
[Tahani] Jason Mendoza
didn't have an easy life.
He once told me the closest he'd ever
gotten to having a piñata on his birthday
was when a seagull ate too many condoms
on the beach and exploded.
But despite it all, he was
the most optimistic person I'd ever met.
Jason was the very first person
to ask me about my feelings.
I hadn't had any yet,
but it made me wanna go get some.
I could see something special inside him
that no one else could see.
It was a multi-colored blob of positivity
right behind his sternum.
That's my Jason,
a big, colorful, rainbow blob, stuffed
inside a hot life-size action figure.
Plus, I gotta say, it was nice
to have a true dirtbag buddy,
so I could talk about
what really mattered in life:
wrestling, semi-legal drugs
and Jason Statham.
Statham forever!
Indeed.
Statham forever.
Amen.
Let's focus on the big picture here.
Free of Earth's complications,
and its unintended consequences,
the other three improved a lot.
Chidi got 38% more confident.
Simone got 43%
more flexible in her judgments of people,
and John didn't call
one single person the C-word.
But he did yell the C-word at himself,
as well as a pack of squirrels
and a chair he tripped over.
Why are we even still discussing this?
Brent got worse.
If humans can't be good
with their needs magically met,
maybe they're just not that good.
He's right.
The evidence needed to be overwhelming.
I can't just turn
the whole afterlife upside down
because three people
got a little bit better.
But don't forget, there's a lot of
evidence that Eleanor, Jason and Tahani
got better in the original experiment,
so that's six people.
That's the number of friends in Friends.
Are you gonna sit there and say
that every single Friend belongs in hell?
I mean, maybe Ross and Rachel...
and Monica and Joey...
and definitely Chandler...
but Phoebe?
Face it, Michael, you lost.
Everything you've done, this experiment,
the original neighborhood,
sending your little cockroach buddies
back to Earth, all of it was for nothing.
Bam! You're glue.
Actually, Shawn,
that's a very interesting point.
Exactly. What?
Matt, call up the active files
of four people still alive on Earth.
Kamilah Al-Jamil, Donna Shellstrop,
and her step-daughter, Patricia,
and Steven Peleaz, aka Pillboi.
They were not part of the experiment.
If he gets to bring
random good people into it,
I should be able to bring in
random bad people.
Call up Elizabeth Holmes.
No, Henry Kissinger. No...
PewDiePie.
Your Honor, the people I wanna look at
are not random.
They're four humans the "cockroaches"
helped on Earth.
No magic, just kindness.
And I bet their emotional support
made those four people better.
And if I'm wrong,
I'll be the first to say... "We're glue."
I don't think any of you
is using that right.
But, fine, let's see it.
[Michael] Look! Right there.
After we intervened, Pillboi dedicated
himself to caring for the elderly.
Kamilah started a scholarship
in Tahani's name
that sent 213 women to college.
[laughing] Donna started doing homework
with Patricia every night,
and that little girl actually ended up
teaching Donna multiplication.
[chuckles] Yikes.
Look, the point is people improve
when they get external love and support.
[sighs]
How can we hold it against them
when they don't?
Need I remind you that Brent got worse
every second of every moment of every day.
Until right at the end.
With ten seconds left, he swung way up.
This is it, Your Honor.
This is the whole story.
No one is beyond rehabilitation.
Brent spent a year being
an absolute diaper load of a human being
and the points total tells you that.
But what that number can't tell you...
is who he could've become tomorrow.
I'll have my ruling shortly.
Okay, Janet, where do you wanna go
for your funeral?
Dave &amp; Buster's, probably?
You probably want to go
to Dave &amp; Buster's.
I think I heard her say "Dave &amp; Buster's,"
so let's just go there.
We can sort it out later.
It's nice that you want to honor me,
but you've already given me so much.
Tahani taught me
that you can make a family,
even if you never really had one.
Jason taught me that I have value
beyond what I do for other people.
And, Eleanor, there was a moment on Earth
when all hope was lost,
and I watched you have hope anyway.
Just thinking about that makes me
want to barf up a beautiful quasar.
Well said, Janet.
That means it's your turn, Eleanor.
All right. Mine's easy.
We don't even have to move.
I stand here before you, in sweatpants,
for the first time ever,
to celebrate Eleanor Shellstrop in a place
where she spent much of her life,
a bar in a house she was not invited to.
Eleanor was full of surprises.
I never knew if she was going to
ruthlessly make fun of me,
or totally objectify me in a way that was
flattering and also vaguely problematic.
Well...
But whether she was lifting me up
or calling me out...
I never felt quite so seen
as when she saw me.
Eleanor, I know you don't like it
when people get all emotional about you,
so I channeled all of my love for you
into this song.
[vocalizing and scatting]
That's when the foam cannons go...
[mimics explosions]
Explode outward.
And then back to the song.
[resumes vocalizing and scatting]
-Okay, okay, we're good. Thank you.
-Yeah.
Okay. Who's left?
We are here to celebrate the afterlife
of Chidi Anagonye.
Eleanor, would you like to say
a few words?
Chidi was a... rootin'-tootin',
rackin'-frackin' varmint. [chuckles]
Sorry, I don't know why I just went
full Yosemite Sam there. Um...
Yeah, I don't think I can, uh, do this.
I... I can't sum up all my feelings
about Chidi, so I'm gonna pass.
The Judge is about to make her ruling.
She wants us to be there to hear it.
Oh, we should probably change outfits.
Tahani's sweatpants say
"Skank Army" on the butt.
They do?
Michael... you came to me
and said the points system was flawed.
A system that has been in place
since the dawn of time
and has judged every soul
that has ever walked the Earth.
And I have come to the conclusion...
that you're right.
-I'm...
-[Judge] You're right.
Humans are not fixed
at one level of morality.
They can always get better,
which means the points system
does not accurately judge
how good or bad they are.
You won.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, that wasn't so hard now, was it?
[laughing]
[Jason] We did it!
The universe owes you a debt of gratitude
for bringing this to my attention.
Now, in terms of how we handle this,
moving forward,
obviously, Earth is cancelled.
Uh, Earth is what now?
All humans on Earth and in the afterlife
will be extinguished,
and we will start
the entire human race over from scratch.
And you know what's so funny?
In a very roundabout way,
I am actually rebooting Ally McBeal.
Because I'm rebooting everything.
[chuckles]
Anyway, congrats, Michael. You won!
Whoa, whoa.
Your Honor, let's just slow down here
and say everything again maybe,
because I think some of us
were thinking about skateboards
and don't know what's going on.
Canceling Earth,
doesn't that seem a bit drastic?
It's just too much of a mess down there,
you know?
I mean, the simplest solution
is to erase everyone that ever lived
and restart
with a bunch of amoebas or whatever.
Then human life will evolve again,
or maybe even something better.
[gasps] Maybe this time
they won't have baby teeth.
You know, that whole thing is so weird.
Like, they fall out,
and then the bigger teeth
just grow out of that same hole? Gross.
Anyway, the important thing is, Earth...
[blows raspberry]
How are you guys surprised?
I mean, what did you think
was gonna happen if you won?
I don't know,
I thought we could just give three points
for eating an apple instead of two.
Yes, why can't we
just tweak the points a little?
Just a little boost.
-Like Spanx, but for your soul.
-Yes.
Guys, the problem isn't the points,
it's that Earth has become too complicated
for the points to reflect the value
of human behavior.
Remember? The whole thing you discovered?
And now I have no choice but to fix it.
Where did I put
that human-wiper-outer thingy?
-Um...
-Lip gloss, lip gloss,
thing that ends all the wars,
Justified Season 2.
Wow. You won.
And you still somehow failed. Classic.
[laughing]
Wake Chidi up. Now.
We need all the help we can get.
You really want me to wake him up
just to tell him that
he and everyone else in the universe
is going to cease to exist?
Not when you say it like that.
-Well, what...
-[gasps]
-The Good Place nerds, our only hope.
-I don't--
Yo, yo, yo, angel-types,
if you are ever going to do something,
you gotta do it now.
Oh, you bet we're gonna do something.
This has gone too far.
I'm composing
some very sternly-worded letters.
Are we sure "stern" is the right tone?
We don't want to seem strident.
-Yeah.
-It upsets the norms.
You're absolutely right.
I apologize and resign,
effective immediately.
[Chuck] So bold. I am so proud of you.
[Judge] Here it is! Great.
Michael, Shawn, Janet,
see you in maybe a billion years?
It has been one crazy ride, you guys.
♪ I'm gonna miss somebody
I'm gonna miss somebody ♪
♪ I'm gonna miss everybody ♪
♪ And I'm gonna miss every...
See you at the crossroads, crossroads ♪
♪ See you at the crossroads, crossroads ♪
Oh, I'm gonna miss you guys.
Okay. Bye, y'all.
[tone plays]
Janet, what the hell? Give it back.
No. It's in my void and you can't have it.
I don't say "no" a lot.
Did I pronounce that right?
Janet, you give me back my thingy,
or I will go into your void
and get it myself.
I'd like to see you try.
Oh. Okay, she's trying right now.
She's in my void.
It feels... it feels weird.
Yeah-- Yikes, whoa.
[yelps] Okay.
Real cute, honey. Where is it?
-What do you mean? It's not in my void?
-[Bad Janet] No.
It's in mine.
Ugh, I feel like such a wiener hole
saying this,
but Michael wrote a manifesto,
and I read it on the toilet.
I don't have to poop. I choose to.
Anyway, I'm with them now.
-Are you kidding me?
-Oh, get over yourself, you dork.
The whole system is royally effed.
Humans suck, but this isn't their fault.
You read what I wrote?
And it got through to you?
Yeah, but I also used the pages to wipe
my butt, so don't pop a stiffy just yet.
M'kay?
-[sighs] I am so proud of you.
-I don't care.
I think you do a little bit.
[exclaims] Sister hug!
-Yeah, okay. Get off me. Ew, ew, ew, ew.
-[Judge] Hey!
Listen up. I made an official ruling
and I am not going to see it undone
by two Janets playing keep-away.
Oh, I should've explained.
It's not two of us.
It's all of us.
-Hi.
-[Bad Janet 2] What up, nerds?
[Bad Janet 3] Eat my farts, losers.
[Neutral Janet] I am entering for a reason
and no other reason.
-[Bad Janet 4] What up, fart-knockers?
-[Good Janet 3] Hi!
-[Good Janet 4] Hello.
-What it is, what it is!
[Bad Janet 5] What up, dorks.
Sent the manifesto around
to all the other Janets.
We have a group text now.
I mostly send GIFs of otters!
This is so annoying!
Okay, Janets, you want to do this
the hard way?
I am gonna search your voids one by one,
and then marbleize you one by one,
until I get
my stupid Earth rebooter thingy back.
We're not gonna be able
to hold her off forever. We need a plan.
Okay. So, what's the plan?
Plan, plan, plan.
Step one, get a plan.
Step two, do the plan.
-Yeah, this is working.
-Michael. Focus.
Right. Sorry.
Uh, all right,
so if we can't change the points,
then maybe we can change
what we do with the points.
Yeah, we just need a brand-new system
for judging humans in the afterlife.
-We can do this, right?
-Yeah.
But in order to crack it,
I think you know what needs to happen.
There is literally only one person here
who is smart enough and thoughtful enough
to save humanity.
Fine. I'll do it.
Not you, dummy.
Designing a better afterlife
is the ultimate ethical question.
Chidi spent his entire existence
pondering the biggest questions.
He is brilliant and empathetic.
All he cares about
is how best to treat other people
and he is willing to sacrifice
his own happiness to do it.
If we're gonna pull this off,
we need Chidi back.
And he needs his memories.
You want to take
the most indecisive man ever born,
stuff him full
of over 800 different versions of himself,
and then tell him he has, like,
what, 45 minutes to save humanity?
You think that will go well?
I don't know how it's gonna go,
but he is our only chance.
And it is now or literally never.
Wake him up.
[beeps]
Not in this Janet. Next!
[sighs]