Not in this Janet. Next!
What are you waiting for? Do it.
It's not that easy.
He lived a whole life,
and then 802 afterlives,
then a second life,
then a second afterlife,
then a third first afterlife...
His psyche's like
a giant bowl of M&amp;M Peep chili.
I gotta make sure all the memories go
in the right place, in the right order.
Maybe I just start him at the beginning.
A full factory reset.
Man. Janet, can I please have a drink
with a lot of alcohol in it?
Here, I saved this from my funeral.
It's called a Duval Ditchwater.
It's Midori, Coffee-Mate and ditch water!
-I'll get you a margarita.
-Yeah, that sounds better.
It's not! Seriously, try this.
-Okay, here we go.
-[Jason] Whoa--
[Ndeye chuckles] Ooh.
[Emeka] He has your eyes.
[Ndeye] And your smile.
-Now, he just needs a name.
-[Emeka] Big decision.
-How about Chidi?
-[Ndeye] Oh, I like that.
Do you like it, Chidi?
Or would you like a different name?
-[crying]
-[Ndeye chuckles] Oh.
Looks like he has a tummyache.
[Emeka] Oh.
[Ndeye] Chidi.
[Emeka] You're not listening to me.
Everything always has to be your way.
[Ndeye] And what is
the one right way then?
I mean, how many times
have I told you this?
[Emeka] I thought
this is what you wanted.
[Ndeye] No!
It's obviously what you want.
You're just angry
that your book was rejected.
[Emeka] How dare
you bring that up again?
[Ndeye] You're always
at the university.
How about you show some interest
in someone who didn't die 200 years ago?
[Emeka] I don't know how much longer
I can keep this up.
We need to go back to Nigeria.
[Ndeye] No, we are not going back.
My family is here
and we did this for your career.
-[Emeka] Oh.
-[door slams]
-Good morning, Chidi.
-Would you like some breakfast?
[Chidi] I have a presentation.
Here's the syllabus.
Take one and pass them on.
My lecture will take
approximately 55 minutes.
Let's begin, shall we?
In conclusion, there is one clear answer,
and it's that the two of you
should stay married.
Questions?
[sighs] That was clear... and persuasive.
And you have made a strong case.
Yes, well-argued. Better than
some of my grad students. [chuckles]
You should get ready for school.
I'll take you.
We'll both take you.
-[Uzo] It worked?
-Perfectly.
They're happy again, Uzo.
They're even talking
about getting me a puppy.
But more importantly,
I proved once and for all
that you can always find the answer.
-The answer to what?
-To anything. Every problem has an answer.
If you just read enough books
and think hard enough,
you can figure out
the answer to any question.
I know you're really smart,
but that sounds wrong.
Children? Please take your seats.
Here's a perfect example.
Where to sit? What's the answer?
Obviously, we want to be back
by the pencil sharpener,
but in the front,
I can see the blackboard better,
or by the door to get a nice breeze?
-Chidi?
-[Chidi] Just hang on.
Sorry.
Oh, no.
I still say Professor Lindeman
was a fool to abandon Chidi.
He has a brilliant mind.
One day, he will use it to solve
the world's biggest problems.
Is this enough cheese?
I hope this is enough cheese.
There's sheep, goat and cow's milk.
-I can run and get more.
-No, this is plenty of cheese. [chuckles]
I have to ask,
has Chidi always been so thoughtful?
Ever since he was a child.
I'm sure you've heard about
his first great lecture?
[chuckling] Oh, no, not that old story
again. It's so embarrassing.
-[Ndeye chuckles]
-Oh. Go ahead.
A long time ago, Emeka and I were
going through a rough patch.
And our little Chidi, at eight years old,
comes in with a one-hour lecture.
[Emeka] All about why
we should stay married.
And all these years later,
here we still are.
-It's the reason I got into philosophy.
-[Allesandra] Hmm.
The biggest questions and the
biggest answers. You just gotta find them.
I mean, I love philosophy, too.
But I'd argue that, say,
theoretical physics presents
bigger questions than philosophy.
[Chidi chuckles]
Do you really think that?
Should I switch to physics?
So, obviously, my parents loved you.
I'm so glad. They're great.
We have to break up.
[stutters] Uh...
What? Why?
I've been feeling this way
for a while now.
It's just... why are we together?
[stuttering] Because it makes sense.
I mean, you like Kant, I like Kant...
-We're not a book group.
-Well, we're not... not a book group.
Okay, if there's a problem
with our relationship,
there is an answer that will solve it.
So, let's hit the library.
You wanna use philosophy?
How about David Hume?
"Reason is and ought only to be
a slave to the passions."
You know, emotions, desires, feelings.
-Do you have any of those?
-Of course I have feelings.
I have strong feelings for you
and what we have.
And right now, I will show you...
how Kant refuted
most of Hume's central theses.
Oh, my God.
[fork rattling in garbage disposal]
-[Chidi] So, what do you think?
-I think it's 3,600 pages.
I have a job, Chidi. I have a family.
Until I had to read this,
I had a will to live.
This work is an insane,
tangled web of inscrutability.
In the fun, "grad students
will analyze this for centuries" way?
No, in the Unabomber way.
Okay. Well, um,
I'll write my way out of the maze.
I'll re-outline the middle chapters,
do more research--
No, Chidi!
You can't answer every question
every philosopher has ever asked.
So, what in these pages do you care about?
-All of it. Equally.
-Shut up!
-But-- Should I--
-Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
The greatest works
of moral philosophy are emotional.
They make an argument
about how the world is and ought to be.
There is a great mind at work in here,
but where is the heart?
Where are the guts?
I understand. I do.
So, I'm going to go home,
and compose a short paper for you,
arguing that I should continue
working on this longer paper.
[Radja] Shut up!
Wow. Tough week. Sorry, pal.
Honestly, I don't know what hurts more,
my thesis meeting or Allesandra.
[sighs] She was brilliant, and funny...
I thought that maybe she was the answer.
Some things in life don't have an answer.
Isn't that what Allesandra was saying?
[chuckling] Isn't that
what your advisor said, too?
Isn't that what everyone
who knows you has said to you
at every waking moment of your life?
Okay, I can figure this out.
I just need to find the answer
for how to impress Allesandra,
a separate answer
for how to impress my advisor
or, ideally, one answer
for how to impress them both.
-Oh, you know what this calls for?
-Don't say it.
-A Venn diagram. Yeah.
-No Venn diagram.
If you won't listen to other people,
do you at least hear what you're saying?
I swear, sometimes it is literally...
...impossible to be your friend.
You're incapable
of making a single decision.
Look, what's the harm in taking
a few extra minutes to find the perfect...
Chidi? Come on in.
Unless you'd be more comfortable out here?
Oh.
Well, I feel like you want me to...
I'll tell you what, I'll decide for you.
Come on in.
Great.
[Michael] Watch this.
Your fridge chooses
your breakfast for you.
Oatmeal and almond milk.
Extra filmy.
You don't even have to decide.
It just knows what you want.
And for all your other requests...
Janet?
-Hi, there.
-[Chidi yelps]
Janet knows the answers
to all the questions in the universe.
Ask her anything.
[chuckles and stutters]
Which answer do I want?
Something profound, obviously.
Shouldn't be trivial or salacious.
Or maybe I should start small,
maybe ramp up.
I... or... I can't... [groans]
-What's the biggest fish?
-The whale shark.
Cool.
I'm sorry.
I'll have better questions later.
You don't need to apologize, Chidi.
All questions are equally important to me.
Oh, well, then,
you and I are gonna get along great.
[Michael chuckles]
I need to go welcome some more residents.
Are there any other questions
I can answer for you before I go?
Well, yes. Is there a relationship
equivalent to the oatmeal?
Uh...
-Is there a, sort of...
-Soulmate?
Yes.
Every person in the Good Place
has one perfect match.
In an hour, come on by the little house
that looks like a face,
and get the answer
to your ultimate question.
Her name's Eleanor.
Oh, man. Remember this?
Yeah! Yeah, that was eight minutes ago.
[Janet] Mmm-hmm.
So, you just proposed to Janet,
-and you said yes, and now you're married.
-[Jason] Mmm-hmm.
[Janet] Mmm-hmm.
You know, I thought saying that out loud
would make it less insane, but it did not.
Thanks, homie.
If you'd like to get us a present,
we're registered at me. [chuckles]
Jason, I think I need your help.
Can I ask you something?
Whoa. No one's ever
asked me for advice before.
And you're a high school principal.
College professor.
Who told you how to do this?
How can you
just make a decision this big?
Chidi, here's the thing with stuff.
You can look at a problem from
every angle and drive yourself crazy,
but sometimes you just gotta huck
a Molotov cocktail at a drone
and see what happens.
Is what happens that the drone blows up?
Usually.
I mean, where I'm from,
most things blow up eventually.
So I learned that when something
dope comes along, you gotta lock it down.
If you're always frozen in fear,
and taking too long
to think about what to do,
you'll miss your opportunity,
and maybe get sucked
into the propeller of a swamp boat.
I just don't think I'll ever be
the kind of person who just... acts.
I mean, I can't just open a door
and walk through
without knowing what's on the other side.
Even with eternity to try,
I just don't think that can happen.
Well, I never thought
I'd ever be able to get married.
I thought I was too old.
I'm infinity, but strange things
happen in the afterlife. [chuckles]
[Eleanor] We figured it out once.
We can do it again.
Because you know what, Michael?
-Ya basic--
-[snaps fingers]
[Michael] This is
your soulmate, Salamasina.
Meet your soulmate, Guan-yin.
Tahani. Karen.
Esmerelda, you don't bring knives
to a friendly game night.
I mean, who does that?
The prepared.
Chidi, Esmerelda, it's your turn!
Blood. Seas of blood.
Enemies.
Uh...
A thousand years of darkness.
-Uh... Nightmares.
-Blood. Ennui?
Lamenting the inexorable passage of time.
Fire and blood. [scoffs]
-[buzzer sounds]
-Ugh! You fool.
It was "birthday parties."
"Birthday parties"?
These trivialities demean me.
I must away and tend to my ravens.
[chuckling] Well, you never know
what'll happen at game night.
Let's continue.
[softly] I think I can find you
another partner.
Tahani, thank you so much.
That ended up being one of the best nights
I've had since we got here.
You and Eleanor made a good pair.
You two really tore through
that round of charades.
Oh, I'm pretty sure she was reading the
cards off the reflection in my glasses,
but, yeah, that was amazing.
[both chuckle]
Um...
-Can I ask you something?
-Hmm.
Tonight could've been a real disaster.
How do you have
the confidence to just swoop in
and so elegantly take charge
of a whole group of strangers?
Honestly, the confidence
comes from failure.
I've thrown my fair share
of disastrous gatherings.
Remind me to tell you someday
about Timothée Chalamet's bar mitzvah.
But you live through the failure
and you learn from it.
Yeah, I just can't operate that way.
I can't make a decision
unless I'm sure I'm right.
Hey, Chidi.
You're a philosophy professor, right?
Any chance you'd want to grab a drink
and talk about ethics?
It's a subject I've recently
needed to learn about, immediately.
-Sounds great. Uh, let me get my coat.
-[Eleanor] Awesome.
By the way, I wasn't cheating before...
or eavesdropping just now.
[Eleanor chuckles] Whoo!
When we started three months ago,
I never thought I'd get so into philosophy
that we'd study past midnight.
[both chuckle]
Esmerelda must be wondering
where her soulmate is.
-Ah. She's off in her aviary.
-Oh.
Sometimes, I think her ravens
are her real soulmate.
[both chuckle]
I'm not kidding, actually.
You should see her with them.
It's intense.
And if I'm being honest, sexually charged.
Anyways. Um...
This has been fun as always--
[sighs] Uh...
What was... Why did you...
Who was it?
[chuckles]
Okay, I'll take those one at a time,
I guess. Um...
It was a kiss.
I did it because I wanted to.
And as far as who it was,
it was me, weirdo.
Eleanor, I have a soulmate.
Yeah, and you're not into her at all.
I mean, come on. There is no way
you're supposed to spend eternity
with a woman who sleeps in a giant nest.
I know she and I are in a rough patch,
but we just have to find the answer
for how to get out of it.
Like my parents.
You remember that story
I told you about my parents?
Yeah, I don't think that story is
as cute as you think it is, man.
I mean, I'm sure you were cute, you know,
big melon head and a little necktie.
But that moment? Woof, that's too much
to put on an eight-year-old.
I kinda wish
cute little Chidi just got to be a kid,
rather than a miniature professor
trying to solve all the world's problems.
Well, but...
living that way led me to philosophy.
And, sure, I was written up
in a medical journal
as the youngest person ever
with a stress-induced ulcer,
but I got into the Good Place.
So, if you don't mind,
I'm gonna take a second to think about
what I owe my universe-approved soulmate,
and not just, uh, make out with you.
Okay, man. Kiss rescinded.
We'll just study, like two platonic nerds,
until Michael discovers me,
or until Esmerelda turns me into a toad
with her magic amulet,
because she can see
that we're obviously into each other.
Oh. Sorry you got an actual human being
instead of your true soulmate...
-a library cart full of damp saltines.
-[chuckles]
You are unbelievable.
I don't know what I did...
-...to deserve you.
-[chuckles]
Believe it, baby. I'm all yours.
At least until
something better comes along.
For me. You've pretty much topped out.
-[Eleanor] You okay?
-No!
I have to give Michael a new draft
of my thesis and I'm a mess. [chuckles]
Will you help me?
Woof! You want my help with philosophy?
You must be in rough shape. [chuckles]
-I mean, yes, of course.
-[sighs]
I'm here for you. What do you need?
I need someone to help guide me,
morally speaking.
And I think I need it to be you.
There's a real possibility
that I'm in love with you again,
here, on this plane of existence,
uh, today, now.
[Eleanor] We found each other before,
hundreds of times.
We can do it again.
Bye, Chidi.
[Michael] You sure you want to do this?
I finally make up my mind
about one damn thing
and you try to talk me out of it?
I'm sure.
Can I ask you a question?
Soulmates aren't real, are they?
Chidi, in all honesty, I don't know.
But I don't think so.
I knew what you expected to find
when you got here: answers.
Also, if I recall from your file,
a magic blackboard?
One that anticipates your lesson flow.
That is the dream.
But mostly you wanted answers.
[inhales and exhales deeply]
The "soulmate" one in particular.
So, I used it to torture you.
Which, again, sorry.
If soulmates do exist,
they're not found, they're made.
People meet, they get a good feeling
and then they get to work,
building a relationship.
Like your parents.
They didn't magically stay together
because you proved they should.
It wasn't my logic or my presentation.
It was the feeling they got watching me,
[chuckles] this scared little kid,
telling them that he needed them.
And it was also
what you made them remember.
They loved each other.
Sometimes, people forget.
You reminded them
of what they already had.
It convinced them to go to counseling.
I never knew they went to counseling.
[chuckles] Yeah, kids are idiots.
If they knew half the stuff their folks
were up to, they'd lose their minds.
[Chidi sighs]
Turns out, life isn't a puzzle that can
just be solved one time and it's done.
You wake up every day
and you solve it again.
Terribly inefficient.
[chuckling] Ah, what a time to learn.
Can you give me a second?
-Janet?
-Hi, there.
Hi.
Uh, can I have a pen and some paper?
I don't know if I'll see you again,
or what I'll remember if I do,
but if we do cross paths again,
sometime, somewhere...
can you get this back to me?
Of course.
[sighs]
I'm ready.
[drink splatters]
Hi, there, Chidi.
Welcome back.
Is he all right? Did you break him?
[Michael] Hey, buddy. How you doing?
Man, I'm doin' great. [sighs]
Hey, so, for the past 300 years,
have I been super annoying?
Oh, no...
-[Michael] No, I wouldn't say... No, no.
-[Tahani] Well, not extremely...
-[Jason] Yes.
-[Chidi] Well, thank you,
all of you,
for everything you've done for me.
You are wonderful people.
Yeah, man, that's great, but, um, listen,
we have one hour to create
an entirely new afterlife
and, uh, also save all of humanity,
and we were wondering if you could do
your Chidi thing and find us the answer?
Oh, well, Eleanor, this kind of thing
doesn't have just one answer.
There might be 800.
There could be zero. Who knows?
The journey is the destination, right?
Let's get to work.
Can you give me one second?
[stutters]
Hey, uh, Janet?
Can I have my note, please?
If you know that you wrote a note
then you know what it says.
I do, uh, but I'd still
like to see it again, please.
I think it might be
some of the best writing I've ever done.