Here is, uh-- Here's my résumé.
Um, I mean, technically
it says, uh, "curriculum vitae,"
which I think is more
professional, but, uh, you know,
same thing, pretty much.
MAN:
That's, uh-- Wow, great.
This position truly is
a no-experience-necessary
kind of thing.
And, uh, it doesn't really
say it here,
but, um, I have
a solid background in, uh--
In sales.
I'm pretty much a self-starter,
so...
That's excellent, but, um--
Excellent.
I just...
I really feel I could be
a major,
major asset to your sales force.
Ah.
I'm thinking there's
a little misunderstanding.
This isn't actually a sales job.
I mean, I'd be happy to consider
you for a sales position,
but all our agents
need to be licensed,
have at least two years
on-the-job experience
and usually a college degree.
Wow.
What you'll be doing
is more like...
advertising.
Hey, Jesse.
Hey, man.
Yo, man.
What up?
Badger?
Where you been
keeping yourself?
Nice duds.
Yeah, you too.
Thanks.
JESSE:
Yo, why would you wanna do
this lame-ass job, anyway?
I mean, no--
No offense.
'Cause I'm on probation,
yo.
I gotta prove to the man
I'm rehabilitated.
Upstanding citizen,
all that shit.
It's really good exercise too.
You can't just stand there,
you have to spin the arrow.
There's all these moves
you have to learn,
like "the helicopter."
[GRUNTING]
Wow.
Yeah. See, yeah?
That one's a bitch.
I'm not very good
at it yet.
You, uh, really opened my eyes
to the possibilities.
Yeah.
Hey, anyways, um,
thanks for the toke.
Any time.
Speaking of which,
you think you could maybe, uh,
hook me up with some crystal?
Uh, no, I've-- I've been out
of the business for a while.
Actually, now thinking
about retiring.
What? No.
Yeah.
That stuff you made
is unbelievable.
It was pretty awesome.
Retirement? Argh!
I can't be hearing this.
No, man, I-I had this, uh--
This partner
who was helping me cook.
I mean, I was doing
most of the work...
[SIGHS]
...but he was an asshole, so.
Anyway, I mean, pseudo's
getting harder and harder
to come by and--
Yo, I can hook you up
with some pseudo.
Major pseudo.
I got channels, bro.
We could partner up.
Huh?
No pressure.
Just think about it, all right?
Oh, shit. I gotta go.
[SIGHS]
Yo, this way to savings.
Save your dollar bills,
y'all.
[SIGHS]
♪ Big savings
This way and save♪
[SIGHS]
Come on! Save some money.
[♪♪♪]
WALT: It's a stupid gift.
SKYLER:
No, it isn't. He'll love it.
I don't know
what I was thinking.
Didn't the invitation
even say "no gifts"?
Walt.
What?
We have to go.
I know, I'm not complaining.
Yes, you are.
Look, we need this.
We've been through a lot
lately. Okay?
Mm-hm.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
SKYLER:
Jesus, guess we didn't get
the "beige" memo.
Ah, we're okay.
Yes, I-- I look like I'm wearing
a prom dress from 1985.
Honey, you look fine.
Walt, this is the only thing
I could find that fit me.
God, would you look at that.
The invitation said "no gifts."
[WHISPERS]
So? Come on.
Sir, I'll take that for you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Oh, look, there's Elliott.
Oh, come on,
let's go say hello.
Elliott. Ha!
Walt.
You made it.
WALT: Ha-ha-ha!
Happy birthday.
Wouldn't miss it for the world.
Thank you. Skyler.
Hi. Oh. Oh, that's right.
Hee-hee-hee!
Great to see you.
You look beautiful, as always.
Well, these days a little
more big than beautiful, but...
Of course, congratulations.
That was such great news.
Thank you.
Gretchen, look who's here.
Oh. Oh.
It's been ages.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Heh!
Ha-ha-ha!
It's really good.
Skyler, welcome.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
It's really nice to be here.
When are you due?
SKYLER: In about 10 more weeks.
And actually, we recently
found out that it's a girl.
Oh, that's so wonderful.
Yeah.
Yeah, we've been thinking
about it for ourselves.
Yeah, thinking about it.
[CHUCKLES]
Uh... Oh, hey, by the way,
uh, securing that patent
was just amazing.
I mean, the work
that your company is doing...
Congratulations
to both of you.
Hard work and a lot of luck.
A lot.
Yeah. Oh, well, now.
MAN:
Elliott.
Will you excuse us?
We gotta say hi.
Make yourselves at home,
we'll catch up later.
Sure, sure. Okay.
Okay.
May I? So glad you're here.
Thank you.
Bye.
John, Missy. How are you?
Shall we?
MAN:
Congratulations.
Happy birthday.
[MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE]
Oh.
Whoa.
Hm.
[COUGHING]
[SIGHS]
[SNIFFS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INAUDIBLE SPEECH]
Walt?
I thought that was you.
Farley.
Ha-ha-ha!
Long time no see.
This is Walter White.
Oh. Hello.
Back at Caltech, he was--
You were just a master
of crystallography.
I remember this one time we were
stuck on this protein problem
for-- For weeks.
You just breezed right in,
and--
And you had one word for us...
Synchrotrons.
It was synchrotrons, yeah.
They generate pure
and more complete patterns
than x-ray beams.
Data collection
takes a fraction of the time.
This is the White
in Gray Matter.
Tell 'em, Walt.
Okay.
Uh, well, back when Elliott
and I were in grad school,
we came up with the name.
Ahem.
Schwartz, black. Walter White.
So together they became
Gray Matter Technologies.
Cute, huh?
So you run the company
with Elliott?
FARLEY:
No. No, that's--
That's Gretchen and Elliott.
Yeah, yeah. You know, I--
I gravitated toward education.
Ah. What university?
Oh, wow, it's a Stratocaster.
Not-- Not just any Strat.
That's one of Clapton's.
ELLIOTT:
No way.
"To Elliott, sorry about
the buckle rash, Eric Clapton."
Thank you.
This is beautiful.
Why is he doing this?
Beautiful.
What is he, like, 8 years old?
Here, honey.
Thanks.
Oh, this is from Walt.
Oh, God.
It's okay.
Hey.
Let's see what we got.
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY]
Yum Good Ramen.
[CHUCKLING]
This is what Walt and I
lived on
for, uh, 10 months straight
while we were working
on our thesis.
Sold them down at Ralstow's
in the hardware isle.
Right next to the-- The--
What was it?
Sterno. Yeah.
The Sterno.
Yeah, ten for a dollar
ninety-nine.
To this day,
I am convinced these noodles
were responsible
for our success.
This was our lifeblood.
Man, where'd you find these?
I thought they'd been outlawed
years ago.
[CROWD CHUCKLES]
I love it.
Thank you, Walt.
Well.
For the man
who has everything.
ELLIOTT: No.
WALT: It was.
No, you remember the fat guy.
Yes.
We used to call him
Snot Trough.
He had that thing
under his nose.
What do you call that thing?
That was Dobkins.
That was the same guy who always
smelled like chocolate milk.
It was.
No, no, no, no.
It-- It wasn't Dobkins,
it was...
Anyway, I swear to Christ,
he used to iron those patches
onto the elbows
of his-- His members-only jacket
because he thought it made him
look more distinguished.
Didn't it? I thought it--
No.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Oh, God.
Well, here's to Snot Trough.
To Snot Trough.
Wherever you may be.
God bless him.
Heh-heh-heh!
Hmmm.
Do you remember
the--? The professor
who used to hate
Robert Wilhelm Bunsen?
Yes. All you had to do
was mention the Bunsen burner
and he was off on a rant.
"Oh, he didn't invent it."
Do you remember the waving?
"He just improved it,"
you know.
Oh. It was easy
to kill 15 minutes.
Yeah.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Oh, God.
I miss this, Walt.
Yeah. Me too.
Listen, uh, we-- We ought
to get together more often.
Skyler and I would love
to have you and Gretchen
over for dinner sometime.
Oh, sure, yeah,
absolutely.
But, you know, what I mean
is that--
That you and I
should work together again.
[CHUCKLES]
Are you gonna teach high school?
No, no, no, seriously.
W-what's stopping us?
Wait a minute, Elliott,
what are you--?
Are you asking me to come work
for you at Gray Matter?
Yeah, why not? You--
You'd fit right in.
You're brilliant, you--
You got a ton of experience.
Well, I...
I wouldn't really know
where to begin.
I mean...
God, you have no idea.
I spend my days just drawing out
atoms on the chalkboard
and trying to get these kids
to learn the periodic table.
Look, I--
I-- I understand.
Y-you're a little rusty,
but you're not seeing
the upside here.
We-- We could really benefit
from a-- A new set of eyes.
You know when you've been
trying to crack some problem
for months on end,
you get tunnel vision.
One guy thinking
outside of the box,
you may be exactly
what we need.
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY]
Well, listen, Elliott, it--
The offer is very appealing,
it really is, I thank you.
But, uh, there's...
There's something
you should know.
I-- I--
I have some personal issues.
Look, there's nothing
we can't work out.
Well, yeah...
but it's--
It's complicated.
We can help you.
We-- We have excellent
health insurance.
The best.
[INAUDIBLE SPEECH]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Um, hey, did you--? Did you try
those prosciutto-wrapped figs?
They were, like, wow.
They were just--
I must have had about 30
of those suckers.
Oh, and the seafood table,
did you see that?
They had lobster tail, they had
crab legs, like, shrimp.
They had...
[SIGHS]
Walt.
What the hell
did you say to Elliott?
What?
You told him about the cancer,
didn't you? Didn't you?
I can't believe it.
Okay, we were talking,
he asked how you were doing,
and I am sorry, but I don't have
the best poker face these days
where that's concerned.
He knew something was wrong
with you, and he pressed me.
He pressed you? Come on.
Walt, when it came
right down to it,
I didn't know what else to do
but tell him the truth.
The truth? Well, how about
you just said, "He's fine," huh?
You could have said that. "He's
fine." It would have been done.
I don't like the way
you're talking.
I don't like the way you talk
about my private affairs
to people who are not
even in our lives anymore.
Well, what exactly
did he say to you?
He offered me a job.
What?
Yes. Kind of like
some fig leaf, you know.
Some face-saving bullshit
that allowed me to
generously accept his charity.
And then when I turned that
down, he flat out
offered to pay
for my treatment.
Which is exactly what you
expected him to do, didn't you?
Walt.
Didn't you?
No. I did not put him up--
Please. Come on. Come on.
[COUGHING]
Okay, what did you say?
Walt?
What do you think I said?
Why? Walt.
[SIGHS]
[CAR DOOR SLAMS]
[CUTLERY CLATTERING]
[INDISTINCT SPEECH OVER TV]
Hm.
Ready to go?
I'm taking the bus.
Okay.
Bye, honey.
[SIGHS]
[DISHES CLATTER]
Hey, dude.
Are these bullet holes?
Uh...
No, man. Those are for,
like, um, you know,
uh, ventilation.
Cool.
Woo.
Nice setup, huh?
Ha-ha!
Man.
This is nothing, man.
I used to have, like,
twice as much glassware
until my, um, dumb-ass
ex-partner drove us into a ditch
and wrecked most of it.
Big-ass beaker, huh?
Hey, wait, wait, no, that's--
Yeah, that's a boiling flask.
This is a beaker.
Here's a Griffin beaker.
Here's a, uh, volumetric beaker.
Here's, uh, an Erlenmeyer flask.
Um, you got--
Wow.
You really know your shit.
It's just basic chemistry, yo.
So...
you got something for me?
Aw, hells, yeah.
Okay.
We're in business.
Right on, Badger.
Dude, check this out.
Jesus.
What are you bringing that for?
Hunting.
We might see javelinas.
[FUJIYA & MIYAGI'S
"UH" PLAYING]
♪ I guess
I wasn't feeling okay♪
♪ I felt that space and time♪
♪ Went back and forth
And sideways♪
♪ I'm putting up fast♪
♪ All over the place♪
♪ I guess...♪
[WHEEZING]
Are you gonna help me or what?
♪ Oh
She made me go "uh"♪
♪ Uh♪
Hey.
♪ Uh, uh, uh♪
♪ Up against and underly♪
Badger!
♪ We are as prickly♪
♪ As a couple of porcupines♪
♪ I'm pulling up fast
All over the place♪
[MUFFLED SPEECH]
Yeah, buddy. Huh? Yeah.
♪ Oh
She made me go "uh"♪
♪ Go "uh"♪
♪ Uh, uh, uh♪
♪ Oh, sock it to me♪
♪ I'm pulling out fast
All over the place♪
♪ I guess
It knocked me sideways♪
♪ Oh♪
♪ She made me go "uh"
Go "uh"♪
♪ Uh, uh, uh
Uh, uh, uh, uh♪
WALT JR.:
Let's see the money.
Here.
I need five each.
Come on, two more.
Here.
What about him?
Are you kidding?
He looks younger than us.
Whatever.
What about
that guy?
No, he looks like a businessman.
BOY:
So what?
So businessmen
are always in a hurry.
They're always, like, going
to some meeting or something.
Seriously,
he's just gonna say no.
BOY:
Hey, hey, this guy.
This is our guy.
You're up.
Wh-why do I have to do it?
Give me the crutches
and I'll go do it.
Shit.
Um, excuse me, hey, um,
we forgot our IDs,
and we were wondering
if you could do us a favor
and buy us a six-pack?
You know,
what you're asking is illegal.
Um...
No, it's not.
Yeah, it is.
Oh, shit.
MAN:
Guess you win the jackpot.
This is not how I wanted
to spend my night off.
Consider this your first
and last warning.
Yes, sir.
You're lucky you got
a good dad, here.
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
The other guys had to run.
I-- I couldn't talk my way
out of it.
Not cool, man. Not cool.
What, you never tried to
buy beer when you were my age?
I'm talking about you calling me
and not your father.
How do you think
that'd make him feel?
[SIGHS]
[CAR STARTS]
SKYLER:
I don't even know
what to say to you.
Just go.
I'll deal with you later.
[EXHALES]
Where's Walt?
I haven't seen him
since this morning.
Your guess
is as good as mine.
Listen, do me a favor,
all right?
Don't tell him about the kid.
He's just a teenager
trying to score some beer.
You know,
growing pains.
I mean, he finds out
his dad's sick,
he starts acting out,
you know?
First the pot,
then this.
The pot?
You told me the kid was smoking.
That's what Skyler told me.
I mean,
you may as well have.
I wasn't talking about
Walter, Jr.
[WHISPERS]
I was--
I was talking about Walt.
Excuse me?
He admitted it.
[WHISPERS]
He said he liked it.
Walt?
Mm-hm.
[LAUGHS]
Shit.
[LAUGHING]
I didn't think
he had it in him.
It's like he's not himself
lately.
Yeah.
I mean,
why would anyone
in their right mind
choose not to do treatment?
Especially when
it's completely paid for.
Why is he doing this?
You know what we need to do?
What we really need to do
is sit him down, all of us,
and-- And get everything out
on the table.
Talk it all through.
You mean an in--? Intervention?
No, no.
Just a family meeting.
Where everyone
can voice their concerns
and be heard.
[WIND BLOWING]
BADGER:
You are a genius, bro.
This cankenstein is unreal.
When we get back, I'm gonna
burn that dollar bill suit,
'cause we're gonna
make some mad dough.
[CHUCKLES]
It's not right.
What do you mean,
it's not right?
Tsk. It's...cloudy.
It's not supposed to be cloudy.
Okay, that last time,
it was glass.
So what? Cloudy, not cloudy?
It looks good enough to me.
Good enough.
Wait, wait.
Yo, what are you doing?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Argh!
Are you out of your mind?
I totally would've
smoked that.
Look, it's not for you,
it's for our customers.
They're gonna demand
a certain standard.
What? What--?
What are you--?
What?
We'll just do it again.
Until we get it right.
[BLOWING]
Walt.
Please have a seat
and join us.
[SIGHS]
We can do better.
Don't you fucking
think about it!
Hey.
Come on.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Three entire pounds
of pseudo wasted.
Do you know how long
I had to spin that stupid sign?
Get off me, psycho.
Helicopter, bitch!
[GLASS SHATTERING]
[GRUNTING]
God! Argh!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Asshole.
[♪♪♪]
Open the door.
[CAR STARTS]
[GRUNTING]
[ENGINE STALLING]
BADGER:
Come back here, you bitch!
I'm gonna mess you up!
This isn't funny!
[GRUNTS]
I really need to understand
your thought process,
because clearly I don't.
I feel that this decision
you've made
is not only
not in your best interest,
it's not in the best interest
of our entire family.
Look, Skyler--
SKYLER: Not yet, please. I--
I have the talking pillow.
Everybody gets to speak
their minds, remember?
And then
you'll get your chance.
Money has always been
an issue for us,
I'll give you that.
But now that Elliott is
more than willing to pitch in--
Walt, I know,
I understand that it's
hard for you to accept help.
Maybe it's the way
you were raised.
But, honey,
it's okay to lean on people
now and again.
You need this treatment.
And nothing can stop you
from getting it
except you.
Am I allowed to respond?
SKYLER: In a minute.
I think we need
to go around the circle first.
Hank, would you like to start?
Uh, yeah. Okay, well...
What I would say is--
Take-- Take the talking pillow.
All right, look, buddy,
um...
I know I don't get to
tell you this enough,
but, uh, I care about you.
A hell of a lot.
And this cancer thing...
Let's just-- Let's face it,
you know,
you were dealt a shit hand.
But, um,
sometimes your luck
can change.
I mean--
I mean, I can't tell you
how many times I was--
You know,
I started with a shit hand,
and I ended up with a, you know,
a full house. Okay?
I mean, the key is,
you gotta hang in there.
Man, you gotta keep
placing your bets,
keep placing your bets.
Boom.
Hank,
what the hell
are you saying?
SKYLER:
No, please, Marie, let him talk.
That's what we're here to do.
Please.
Go on, Hank.
All right, l--
Look at it this way, okay?
It's the bottom of the ninth,
bases are loaded,
you're up.
But you got a bum arm,
right?
There's no fricking way
you're gonna hit a homer, okay?
So you can either let
the pinch hitter take the bat,
or you can hold on to your pride
and lose the game.
You get what I'm saying?
No.
You got your pride, man.
I get it, okay? I get it.
But this Daddy Warbucks
wants to chip in, man.
I'm-- I'm with your old lady
on this one.
[LAUGHS]
I say take the money and run,
man.
[SNIFFS, SIGHS]
Somebody wanna take this thing?
Here.
Y-yes, Walter--
Walter, Jr., I'm-- I'm sure
that you have about a million
things to say, probably.
And now is your chance.
Go ahead. Just let it all out.
This is bullshit.
All right, come on.
SKYLER: It's all right.
It--
[SIGHS]
Talk.
Tell your dad how you feel.
I'm pissed off.
Tell him.
I-I'm pissed off.
'Cause you're being--
You're being...
Y-you're--
[SIGHS]
You're a pussy.
You're, like, ready to give up.
You're-- God.
What if you gave up on me, huh?
This here,
all the stuff
I've been through,
and y-you're scared
of a little chemotherapy?
Me, personally...
I think you should do
whatever you wanna do.
What?
You told us to be honest
about our feelings.
Walt's the one with cancer,
it's his decision.
It's not up to any of us.
Why in hell would you do this?
Hey, hey.
I wasn't planning
on agreeing with Walt.
But after sitting and listening
to you all talk about his future
like he has no say in it--
He's not gonna have a future
if he doesn't get treatment.
I am a medical professional.
Ugh.
I x-ray people in treatment
every day.
I see them every day.
And you know what?
Some of them
are absolutely miserable.
Marie--
I'm sorry, but it's true.
And some of them don't wanna
spend their last weeks or months
being picked at by doctors.
But they got talked into it
by their families.
Can I get the pillow back?
'Cause I agree with Marie.
Thank you.
SKYLER: Hank--
What? Maybe Walt wants to die
like a man, all right?
I don't want him to die at all!
That's the whole point of this.
So either help or leave!
Skyler, I just wanted
to do you the courtesy
of giving you my honest opinion.
You know, Marie,
this is not debate club.
This is my husband's life--
I made one simple observation--
And it's like you-- How dare
you--
Okay, so we disagree--
Ladies! Marie!
[WHISTLES]
This is so stupid.
All right,
I've got the talking pillow now.
Okay?
We all, in this room,
we love each other.
We want what's best
for each other, and I know that.
I am very thankful for that.
But what I want--
What I want,
what I need...
is a choice.
What does that mean?
Sometimes I feel like I never
actually
make any of my own choices,
I mean.
My entire life...
it just seems I never...
you know, had a--
Had a real say about any of it.
Now, this last one, cancer...
all I have left is
how I choose to approach this.
SKYLER:
Then make the right choice,
Walt.
You are not the only one
it affects.
What about your son?
Don't you wanna see
your daughter grow up? I just...
Of course I do.
Skyler, you've read
the statistics, you...
[SIGHS]
These doctors
talking about "surviving"
one year, two years,
like it's the only thing
that matters.
But what good is it
to just survive
if I am too sick to work?
To enjoy a meal?
To make love?
For what time I have left,
I wanna live in my own house.
I wanna sleep in my own bed.
I don't wanna choke down
30 or 40 pills every single day
and lose my hair
and lie around,
too tired to get up...
and so nauseated
that I can't even move my head.
And you.
Cleaning up after me.
And me? What--?
Some, uh--
Some dead man,
some artificially-alive--
Just marking time.
No. No.
And that's
how you would remember me.
That's the worst part.
So that is my thought process,
Skyler.
I'm sorry. I just...
I choose not to do it.
[♪♪♪]
All right.
"All right" what?
I'll do the treatment.
[PAN CLATTERS]
[SIGHS]
It's gonna be okay.
Okay.
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER PA]
[DOOR OPENS]
Um, the lady
from the billing office
said they usually bill
the insurance company directly.
But since our HMO's
not paying for it,
we can pay up front
with a credit card.
Oh, good.
Oh, and then Elliott
will send a check. Right.
I will take care of it.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Walter White?
Yes.
Okay. Heh-heh!
All right.
Okay.
See you in a minute.
WALT: Okay.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
[MACHINERY WHIRRING]
[MACHINERY BEEPING]
[♪♪♪]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[CAR DOOR SLAMS]
[PHONE BEEPS]
Ha-ha! Elliott.
GRETCHEN:
Walt, it's Gretchen.
Oh, hey.
Hey, Gretchen, how are you?
You know, it was--
It was really great
seeing you two
the other day, you know.
Wow, what a party.
Um, Elliott told me
about the cancer.
I-I-I'm-- I'm so sorry.
Well, you know,
it is what it is, I guess.
I don't--
I don't know what to say.
Except, I'm always here for you.
Both of us are.
We wanted you to know that.
Yeah, well, thank you.
Walt, Elliott told me
that he'd offered to pay
for the treatment.
You have to accept.
That money,
as far as we're both concerned,
that-- That belongs to you.
Even the name of our company,
it-- It's-- It's half yours.
Walt?
Is this about you and me?
Gretchen, I really appreciate
the offer.
I do. Um, but we're fine.
Uh...
As it turns out,
the insurance came through
after all.
So, um,
I am covered. And, uh...
Well, and, anyway,
I-I-I really appreciate it,
I really do.
Thank you.
Good. That's good news.
You know, that really was a--
A great party.
Keep in touch, okay?
Sure. Sure, and...
thank you for calling.
[PHONE BEEPS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[SCOFFS]
Yo!
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Wanna cook?
[♪♪♪]