[WIND BLOWING]
[♪♪♪]
[BENNY MARDONES' "INTO THE
NIGHT" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey, Captain America.
What's up, brother?
Hey, bro.
[POLICE RADIO SQUAWKING]
[DOOR CHIMES BEEP]
[SIGHS]
This is stupid.
WALT:
You got a better idea?
Okay, fun. Whatever.
So when do we, you know?
WALT:
We don't, for now.
No cooking
until things settle down.
Settle down?
I thought you're the one
that said
nothing's changed.
Look, I just put my family
through an ordeal
that they're just now starting
to accept, okay?
I can't--
Uh. That's too expensive.
Look, I can't leave
my house
for more than 20 minutes
without my wife worrying.
I need time
to mend fences.
Okay, so while you're fixing
fences, what about me, huh?
Your A-hole brother-in-law
took all my money.
That's $600.
Okay, what about the rest?
Rest of what?
Half your money's mine.
Fifty-fifty partners.
That's our business motto.
Meaning what, exactly?
That I suffer
for your carelessness?
You're the one who wanted
to work with Tuco, okay?
If it weren't for that,
none of this would've happened.
[DOOR CHIME BEEPS]
Just be cool. We'll talk
about this later, okay?
As for now, no contact.
Understood?
Whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
I leave first.
[SIGHS]
Walt!
WALT:
In the kitchen.
Hey.
Hey. I didn't know you were
allowed to touch the stove.
Hilarious, Groucho.
Go on, grab a seat.
Juice is on the table.
What?
SKYLER:
Mm, oh, good morning, honey.
Hey, Mom.
Dad's cooking breakfast.
But don't worry.
I'm also doing all the dishes.
Huh? Huh? Eh?
Nice? Follow me.
There's also orange juice
and grapefruit juice,
which, personally, as you know,
I've never been a fan of.
But considering
all the polyphenols
and the limonoids,
can't hurt.
Walt, you didn't
have to do this.
I wanted to.
Grapefruit juice?
Yes, please. Thanks.
There you go. Honey?
Um, no, I'll stick with orange,
thank you.
All right, well,
dig in, dig in.
Pancakes are not
getting hotter.
Wow.
Yeah.
[LAUGHS] There you go.
WALT:
All right. Got one. Steely Dan.
Uh, no.
Yes, absolutely.
No, in terms of
pure musicianship,
I would put them up against
any current band you can name.
You wouldn't know
any current bands.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
That's besides the point.
Have a good day, honey.
You too.
Ah! Boz Scaggs.
There's another one.
Ugh! Boz Scaggs.
Mm-hm.
Whoever they are.
Bye. Thanks for breakfast.
Bye.
You're welcome.
Listen, tell Louis
to drive carefully.
All right.
[CHUCKLES]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Our son doesn't know
who Boz Scaggs is.
We have failed as parents.
Come to think of it,
I barely know who Boz Scaggs is.
Stop it.
Give me your plate.
No, no. I'll get it.
I'll get it. Yeah.
Thank you.
Mm-hm.
Hey, uh, listen,
in the calendar section
um, all week long
there's a fiction writer's
seminar at UNM.
And, you know, probably talking
about how to get published
and that sort of thing.
Yeah?
Mm-hm.
Hm.
Yeah, so, anyway,
I thought maybe you might...
I mean, I'll go with you
if you like.
Oh, and, uh,
you know,
I was thinking about
what you asked me
the other night.
You know, you were wondering
if I had a second cell phone.
And, well, I've been
thinking about that a lot,
and I think what you heard
was my cell phone alarm
going off.
Yes.
I've been using it a lot
as a medication reminder
to, uh, well, remind me
to take my medication.
And, uh, well,
the weird thing is that
the alarm sound
is almost exactly the same
as the regular phone ring
which is really a poor design,
if you ask me. But I think
that was probably it.
I tried to go in and change it
to a different sound
other than the phone ring,
but...
They so overcomplicate
these things.
Anyway, it was, uh, probably
just as well that I lost it.
There's got to be a new one
on the market by now.
You know, if we do this thing
at UNM, maybe on the way home
we can stop by,
and I can get a new cell phone.
[DOOR SLAMS]
Skyler?
[CAR DOOR OPENS AND SLAMS]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
Skyler?
[DIALING]
[LINE RINGING]
[BUZZING]
[SNIFFS]
Ready?
Yo, for what, might help.
[SIGHS]
Not another
intervention.
GARDINER:
Jesse Bruce Pinkman,
pursuant to Section 47-8-13
of the New Mexico
Real Property Code,
you are hereby
given notice to vacate
the premises listed
as 9809 Margo,
Albuquerque, 87104.
Wait. What? You're kicking me
out of my own house?
It's your aunt Ginny's house.
And she gave it to me.
She never
gave it to you, Jesse.
GARDINER:
You were allowed
residentiary privileges.
Your parents have always
been the property owners.
Look, we talked about this,
okay?
I'd sell the house,
we'd split it fifty-fifty.
That was the deal.
What the hell happened?
What happened is
you're a speed manufacturer.
No, I'm not. What?
MRS. PINKMAN:
A DEA agent came
looking for you, Jesse.
He came to our front door.
Okay, because I've actually
been helping them,
which I could get into a lot
of trouble for telling you,
so you're welcome.
I saw your basement.
Oh, yeah.
I was worried, so I went
over there and I let myself in,
and I found your laboratory.
You guys have your own key?
[SCOFFS]
Manufacture of a Schedule II
controlled substance
is a second-degree felony.
Under federal asset seizure,
the government can take
the entire house.
It's not even there anymore.
I cleaned it all out.
Son, we can't stop you
from ruining your life,
but you will not drag us down
with you.
GARDINER:
Vacate the house in 72 hours.
Otherwise, your parents
have authorized me
to contact the authorities.
Is that clear?
Do you have
any questions for us?
Three days, Mr. Pinkman.
Come on.
[CAR APPROACHING]
[CAR DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
Hi.
Hey.
Hey, I, uh,
fixed the garage door.
Great.
Yeah.
One track was bent.
That's why it was bouncing.
Okay.
Where were you today?
Out.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine.
Hey, you know,
for what it's worth,
I was thinking about going
back to those meetings,
the cancer support group.
I think that that's good.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, that's good.
Uh, you were-- You were right
on the money about that.
Yeah, that's--
It's good to, you know,
talk about things.
I think that's great.
Yeah.
[WATER RUNNING]
MRS. PINKMAN:
Jesse.
Jesse. Hey, Jesse.
[GASPS]
You don't answer
your phone?
[SIGHS]
Yeah, no, I've just been
pretty busy.
How'd you--?
Oh, right,
you have that key.
Um, hey, listen. Um...
So I've been thinking
a lot about our conversation
we had the other day,
and I-- I completely get
why Dad totally tweaked off
on me like that and...
It's not just your father,
Jesse.
No, I-- I-- I know.
I know. I know.
I'm just saying it was,
you know, a really,
really big wake-up call for me,
you know,
which is why I wanted
to talk to you.
You know, I've been
thinking real seriously
about business school,
actually.
You can do the whole thing
from your computer now...
No, Mom, Mom.
Hey, hey, this is good.
You know, we're talking,
starting a dialogue.
The time for talking
has passed, Jesse.
Hey. Hey.
What the hell, yo?
I thought this was just
a wake-up call.
We are putting it
in storage.
When you decide to grow up,
you can have it back.
Why don't you grow up, Mom?
Ginny wanted me here.
All right?
I was the one
who took care of her.
I took her to her appointments
and made her lunch every day.
I earned this.
You did not make
her lunch every day.
What did you do, huh?
She's lying there dying,
and where the hell are you?
Don't start with me.
Now what?
You've decided to,
oh, I don't know,
make your eldest son
homeless?
Wow! Great family, Mom.
Why are you like this?
Why?
You have two sets of keys
and the padlock to the garage.
Leave them on the kitchen
counter when you leave.
No, Mom, Mom, Mom.
Hey, where am I
supposed to go?
I don't know, sweetheart.
But please
turn your life around.
Yeah, this is gonna help
big time with that. Bitch!
Jeez.
[SIZZLING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Oh, hey, Mr. White.
Hey, well, now,
that's the way.
Don't just sit out there
honking.
Come in and say hello.
Hey, we've got omelets.
You want an omelet?
No, I'm good.
New Mexican Christmas style,
red and green chilies.
No. Thank you, though.
Flynn and me
gotta get going.
Who's Flynn?
Flynn.
He's your, uh...
Flynn?
Yeah.
So?
So? Nothing.
You ready?
Like it.
Bye, Mr. White.
Okay.
Bye.
Flynn? You know about
this Flynn thing?
Mm-hm.
Huh?
Okay. Flynn. Yeah.
As in what, Errol?
I don't know. It's what he likes
to be called these days.
What's wrong with
Walter Jr.?
Don't take it personally.
He wants his own identity.
You think he-- He told Louis
about me?
About the blackout?
Louis is his friend, Walt,
and your disappearance
upset him.
Hey, I made omelets.
[PHONE RINGING]
I'm going out,
but thanks, though.
Where you going?
[PHONE RINGING]
Can you
get the phone, please?
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
White residence.
JESSE:
Yo, it's me.
Is this a good time?
What part of "no contact"
didn't you understand?
I know, but there's a problem.
I don't care. We agreed.
No amount of pay-per-view
channels
is gonna make
any difference.
Honey, we're happy
with our cable provider, right?
Yeah, we're happy.
Skyler? Sky?
Where are you going?
Can you at least tell me that?
Out.
[PHONE RINGS]
Ooh. Should probably
get that, Walt.
I'll be back
in a few hours.
Skyler.
[PHONE RINGING]
What?
Yo, I get I shouldn't call,
but I'm in a situation over here
and I need my money.
I just gave you $600.
Yeah, and thanks,
Daddy Warbucks,
but that was
before my housing situation
went completely
testicular on me, okay?
You smoked the entire 600,
didn't you?
What? No.
Yes.
No.
Look, Jesse,
your problems are just that:
Your problems.
No contact.
Do not call here ever.
When the moment is right,
I will call--
Mr. White,
you're not listening.
They're kicking me out
of my house.
God!
[LINE RINGING]
[PHONE RINGS]
You son of a bitch.
Uh! Son of a bitch.
Oh, hey, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thanks, man. Oh, hey, guy!
You forgot something! Yeah!
You forgot your ice trays!
You're gonna need the ice trays!
Hey, you forgot something here!
Take this!
[BASS GUITAR BEING PLAYED]
♪ Black is the color ♪
♪ But beauty is the game ♪
♪ The beasties come
To get me ♪
♪ But I don't feel
The pain ♪
♪ Fallacies, fallacies ♪
[MICROWAVE BEEPING]
Hold on, buddy.
Yo, we should get Twaughthammer
up and running again, yo.
I'm serious.
I know.
That sounded tight.
Hey,
thanks again, P.
I made sure this stucknut
exterminator, you know,
put me on his speed dial.
Two nights tops.
Oh, no, hey,
you still staying
at your aunt's on Margo?
Yeah. I'm thinking of moving.
Nob Hill, probably.
Jess-a-matic.
Living the dream.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Okay, buddy. You're gonna
eat your carrots
like we talked about,
right?
Too hot.
No, no, buddy.
Remember. Okay?
Come on, yes.
Listen, hey,
talk to me, man.
Are you still having
mad relations out there?
You can talk to me.
I won't hate a player.
I can't lie. It's pretty hectic
out there, female-wise.
[SIGHS]
Damn. I'm hating, man.
See, that's why we need
to get the Hammer
up and running,
you know?
Get you out of the house.
How awesome would that be?
Come on. Look. What?
Hm?
I cut all the green parts
off like you--
Just eat them. Please?
We-- We should do this.
You know, track down Cheevo
and Anthony and demo up.
Get back in the scene.
I'm sorry, man. Just hold on
one second, all right?
Okay, listen. How about you take
a bite of your sandwich,
and then you take--
[DOOR OPENS]
Mommy's home.
Hi.
Hello.
Hey, honey, you remember
Jesse Pinkman?
His house is getting
bug bombed
and I said he could crash
a few nights.
Hey, Jesse.
Hey.
Paul, could you help me
in the bedroom with these?
Sure. Yeah.
[SIGHS]
Yeah, I used to
not like carrots too.
SARA:
Hey, Hen,
I think it's someone's
nap time.
Come on.
[CHUCKLES]
Man, oh, dude, you're gonna--
You're gonna kill me.
I totally spaced
that the in-laws
are crashing this weekend.
You got other people
to call?
Hey, no, that's-- That's cool.
I got tons of people. Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yo, in-laws?
Sucks to be you, P.
Yeah. Yeah, I know, huh?
Here.
See you, man.
It's good to see you.
Look, I'm asking to crash three,
maybe four nights, and--
Look, I already called Badger,
all right? I called everyone.
I need a solid here, bro.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
whatever.
[SIGHS]
All right. All right.
Hey, how about this?
[SIGHS]
What if it's just
for tonight?
[GRUNTS]
[MUMBLING]
[SIGHS]
Wait. No, you cannot
be serious.
You cannot be serious!
Hey.
Someone took your bike, man.
Not cool.
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[YELLING AND GRUNTING]
[LIQUID SLOSHING]
[JESSE SCREAMING]
[COUGHING]
[GASPING]
[WHIMPERING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[CRIES]
[COUGHS]
[COUGHING]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
Morning.
Oh, hey.
Um...
Where did--?
Where did Mom go?
Out.
Um, where's breakfast?
Hey.
Let's go do something.
Uh, like what?
Something fun.
WALT:
All right, ready?
Let's, uh, put it in gear.
Is your foot on the--?
Okay. Good.
Yeah. I got it.
Good.
Yes. Nice and smooth.
Good. Just like that.
Good. I like the hands
at 10 and 2. Very nice.
Okay, let's slow down here
to a stop in preparation
for a left-hand turn. Okay.
All right. You might want
to go easier on the brake.
Sorry about that.
That's okay.
All right.
You're doing fine.
Much better
than last time, huh?
Oh, yeah,
Louis has been helping me.
Has he?
Good. Good. Okay.
Don't forget the turn indic--
Good.
I'll stop talking.
You know what you're doing.
And let's make
that left-hand turn.
Nice and smooth. Very nice.
Right hand.
Good. Good. Okay.
Oh, are you using both feet?
Yeah.
No. Wait. Wait. No, Walt.
You can't do that.
You can't use one foot
on each pedal.
Why not?
Because you can't.
Stop, Walt, okay?
Just stop, please.
Right. All right.
Dad, this is way easier.
Come on.
There's the easy way,
and then there's the right way,
right?
So let's just try it again,
right foot only.
All right.
Okay?
Okay, just-- You don't have to--
Okay. All right. That's fine.
Just-- That's okay. That's okay.
Just try it again.
Here we go.
Let's just, just try it again.
Okay.
[TIRES SCREECH]
Don't-- Just easy.
Okay, okay, good. Great.
That was better. See?
Right? Better? Right.
The gas, the brake,
the gas, the brake.
I can't do this.
My legs don't work that way.
Your legs are fine.
You just have to stick with it.
Don't set limits for yourself,
Walt. You're all right.
All right. We'll get this.
I promise.
Now let's just try again,
all right?
All right.
Here we go. Here we go.
Okay, well, you don't need to,
you know, just take off.
But all right, here we go.
Slow it down just a little bit.
All right, we have a turn
coming up here,
so prepare
to apply the brakes.
Prepare, Walt, for the brakes.
Brakes, the brakes.
I'm braking.
You're using both feet again.
It's not stopping.
That's the gas. Use the brake.
The brake.
Brake, brake, brake!
Okay.
That's one way to stop.
I told you.
Flynn.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[GUN COCKING]
MAN: Hands up, asshole!
Yo, yo, it's cool.
So help me, I will spread you.
No, please, no, all right?
It's me, okay? It's Jesse.
All right?
Look, this is my RV.
You towed it.
Your cousin Badger, remember?
What the hell
are you doing here?
You smell like shit.
It's a long story.
So I fixed up your felonious
rolling laboratory here,
750 for the repair.
Make it a grand,
counting the toilet
plus the 500
you already owe me,
and you're good to drive on
out of here
to someplace far away.
Upwind.
Okay, um...
Here's the thing.
I can't pay you today.
But I can pay you this week,
all right?
Seventeen fifty?
We'll make it 1750,
for, like, you know,
interest.
I thought your word
was your bond.
No, it totally is.
Definitely. I just don't
have the money
at this particular moment.
But I will, soon.
Here's my counteroffer.
I kick you out. I take payment
from your inventory.
I know a guy that'll pay
premium for this kind of crap.
All right.
Two grand. Okay?
Two days, 2 grand.
That's totally fair.
Just don't take my cook stuff.
All right?
That's all I got left.
Please, all right?
I really...
God, I really need
a break here.
Okay?
Clovis, come on.
I don't know. There's a bunch
of stuff in there.
There's something called
methylamine. Me-- Meth...
However the hell
you pronounce it.
Methylamine.
I don't know. I banged on it.
It sounds pretty full to me.
Holy shit. How much?
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SCREECH]
Hey! Hey!
[SHOWER RUNNING]
WALT:
Skyler.
Louis took Walt to school.
I was thinking maybe
this would be
a good time to talk.
I dreamt that I owned
an antique bicycle repair shop.
In Ireland.
Weird.
Sounds weird.
I wanted to apologize.
For everything.
My
desire for privacy.
My emotional
unavailability.
Having cancer
doesn't excuse all that.
I haven't been
a good partner to you,
and for that,
I'm very sorry.
I love you.
And I love this family.
And I just
want to make sure that
we don't lose contact.
Thank you.
Okay.
I agree.
Is that it?
Oh, God.
God, how long are
you gonna do this?
Do what?
This.
Not-- Not talking to me.
Going out all day and--
And refusing to tell me where.
You are obviously angry with me
about something,
so let's talk about it.
Oh, God.
I feel like you're upset with me
because you think that
I'm up to something.
Like what?
I have no idea, Skyler.
What, that I'm having an affair?
Is that it?
Is that what you think?
Is that why you asked me
about the...
Some other phone?
Because you think
that I'm being unfaithful?
I don't know.
Okay.
So ask me.
Why?
Would you even tell me?
Yes. I would.
Of course I would.
And no. I'm not.
I'm not having an affair, okay?
Now, what do I do
to prove that to you?
Swear an oath? Okay.
My right hand to God.
I'm not having an affair.
I heard you, Walt.
You're not having an affair.
Congratulations.
No, you know what?
Congratulations to you, Skyler.
Great job.
Mm-hm.
I mean, what is this?
What do I have to do?
I'm trying to talk to you,
and you--
Okay, so talk, Walt.
Shut up and say something
that isn't complete bullshit.
You want to know
what you have to do?
You have to tell me what's
really going on right now.
Today. No more excuses.
No more apologies.
No more of these--
These obvious,
desperate breakfasts.
You don't want to lose
contact with me, Walt?
Good.
Then tell me.
Now.
Tell you what?
Skyler.
What is it you want me
to tell you? I don't know.
We're not done here. Skyler.
Do you know what
I've done for this family?
[ENGINE STARTS]
What the--?
[TIRES SCREECH]
Yo, I'm really sorry, okay?
What is wrong with you?
Why are you blue?
Oh, Jesus.
I'm sorry.
Let's just say it starts
with my parents being greedy,
kleptomaniac douche bags.
Are you actually
this stupid?
No, look.
I know this isn't a optimal--
To come to my house and park
on my street,
driving this vehicle.
I mean, what the hell is wrong
with you?
I'm-- I'm really asking.
Nothing. I'm sorry. I just--
What if Skyler
had seen you, huh?
What then? What was
the plan then, genius, huh?
I don't know.
You don't know.
You know why you don't know?
Because you don't think.
That's why.
You don't think. You never
figured out
how to think, did you, Pinkman?
Hey, I said I was sorry.
I just need my half
of the money, and I will go.
Your half?
There is no your half
of the money.
There is only my all of it.
Do you understand?
Why--? Why should I be penalized
because of your sloppiness?
Look, that is completely uncool,
all right?
We agreed,
fifty-fifty partners.
Partners in what?
What exactly do you do here?
I've been meaning to ask,
because I'm the producer, right?
I cook. But from what
I can tell,
you are just a drug addict.
You are a pathetic junkie,
too stupid to understand
and follow
simple rudimentary
instructions.
Too stupid to re--
[GRUNTING]
[CHOKING]
[PANTING]
Do it.
[COUGHING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Try not to touch anything.
[♪♪♪]
Want some breakfast?
[DOOR CHIME BEEPS]
[SIGHS]
♪ And ever day is the same ♪
♪ Since I met you ♪
♪ It's such a pretty world
Today ♪
♪ Knowing that you're mine ♪
♪ Knowing you're mine ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ And happiness
Is being close to you ♪
♪ And though the rain
May fall ♪
♪ Our skies are always blue ♪
♪ If I look close enough ♪
♪ The sun will come
Shining through ♪
♪ It's such a pretty world
Today ♪
♪ Look at the sunshine ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Today and every day ♪
♪ Since I met you ♪
[♪♪♪]