[MAN 1 SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[MAN 2 SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[♪♪♪]
[PEOPLE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY]
DELCAVOLI:
Well, we've come
a long way, Walt.
Here at the end of round one,
I'm gonna recommend
cautious optimism.
We'll check back in two months,
see how you've responded,
reassess and decide
our next move, if any.
That's right around the time
the baby's due, correct?
Uh, yeah.
Well, try to think of this
as good timing.
You'll start feeling better
soon, more like yourself.
And your hair should start
to come back.
Ah.
Kind of gotten used
to the old cue-ball look.
I prefer to think of it
as streamlined.
Right. Aerodynamic.
So no more confusion?
No more--?
No. No. Absolutely none.
How are you two holding up?
Fine.
I mean, you know,
we're busy,
but we're good.
Absolutely.
It's all good.
So we're not going through
an insurer, is that correct?
Yes. Direct bill.
Just need to print it out
for you.
[PRINTER BEEPS]
Thank you.
Um...
I thought we had discussed
a cash discount.
Absolutely. It's included.
Just a reminder.
We do have
a payment plan available,
should you be interested.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
SKYLER:
Okay, well, then
what about the MRI?
Can you--?
Can you please explain to me
the distinction between
diagnostic and exploratory?
Yeah, but either way,
his doctor ordered it.
Okay, you know,
it should be covered.
You bet I will.
Yeah, in triplicate.
Okay. Well, I'm sorry you
couldn't be of more help too.
Yeah. Okay.
[PHONE BEEPS OFF]
Bitch.
Hi.
Been around someone
who smokes?
No.
The hospital bill came.
That was fast.
Yeah.
Three-day stay,
13,000 and counting.
[SIGHS]
Is this something that Gretchen
and Elliott might cover?
I mean,
I, uh, I know it's strictly
your domain, but, um...
They will.
I-- I'm sure they will.
I'll handle it.
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[RETCHING]
[FLUSHES]
Oh, crap.
[KNOCKING]
Bring me up to speed on
Tuco Salamanca.
Dead.
Still?
Completely.
Okay, then.
Well, thanks for stopping by.
Okay.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Oh...
So things are quiet,
you know.
Not a lot of crystal
on the streets now.
Good.
Of course, that's not
gonna last.
Waiting to see who'll
rally the roaches
now that his turf's
up for grabs.
No takers so far?
Well, we keep hearing a name.
Heisenberg.
Lately pretty much every
dime-bagger we come across.
Heisenberg?
Yeah, I know.
Maybe it's a tweaker
urban legend.
Still, somebody somewhere
is cooking that big blue
we keep finding.
Anyway, uh,
we'll stay on it.
Know why sharks are at the top
of the food chain, Hank?
Because they have
three sets of teeth
and will take a bite
out of anything?
Some of those suckers
travel thousands of miles
in pursuit of their prey.
Yeah, I, uh,
I think I heard that.
You, my friend,
are a great white.
How does Albuquerque liaison
Tri-State Border Interdiction
Task Force sound?
Like one hell of a promotion.
As of the 1st,
I want you to split your time
between here and El Paso.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
What you gonna do without me,
Gomey?
Celebrate. I won't have
to look at your ugly mug
six days a week.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Hey, buddy,
I am the brains and the brawn.
I'm the whole package.
I'm glad I didn't just eat.
I'm surprised your head
still fits through the door.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hey, you wanna grab lunch?
Hell, yeah.
Because you're buying.
Done. I'll meet you morons
downstairs.
Try not to get lost on the way.
Schrader.
Yeah. Hey, Ricky.
How you doing?
Yeah, I'm stoked too.
Yeah, El Paso.
[SNAPPING FINGERS]
AGENT:
Here's the man.
Hey, congratulations, Hank.
Thanks.
[HUMMING]
[ELEVATOR WHIRRING]
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
[DINGS]
[SIGHS]
GOMEZ:
Gets two in the sand,
two in the forest, you know?
And then he says,
"Give me a four," you know?
HANK:
Hey. Hey.
[BRAKES SQUEALING]
[TRAILER DOOR OPENS]
Hey.
You got some nerve
coming back here.
Or you're even dumber
than I thought.
Yeah, well, uh,
maybe both.
Balance for the tow,
the repairs,
and extra for damages
and stuff, the gate,
the toilet.
Look, like I said,
my word is my bond.
[SIGHS]
What would you charge me
to store this here?
A million-five.
Come on, yo.
Your sister.
Dog, I'm serious, all right?
I got storage needs.
And I got scratch up front.
We could, you know, negotiate.
Five hundred.
A month?
A week.
For real?
See you.
Wait, wait, wait.
Just hold on.
Just chill.
Okay. Sounds good.
Totally doable.
Outside.
Inside.
Forget it.
Man, come on.
Your fence is too easy
to climb.
[SCOFFS]
Inside, padlocked,
plus gate privileges.
Come again?
Gate, in and out,
privileges.
Month to month.
Cash up front.
Inside.
And I don't know you.
I don't know jack.
Yeah.
You selling?
I'll let you take it
for 9 Gs.
[SIGHS]
What about that one?
Serious?
[JOHNNY RINGO'S "HOOK 'EM HORNS"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
JESSE:
It's Jane, right?
Well, Jane, I gotta say,
this place is awesome.
Really? Does it inspire awe?
No. I mean, you know,
it's great.
Just what I've been looking for.
That's what I meant. Uh...
I had an entire house before,
detached and all,
but, you know, I was just tired
of the lawn care,
upkeep and whatnot.
You know?
Well, the blinds are new.
Everything's been painted.
[GARBAGE DISPOSAL WHIRS]
Jesus.
Utilities are included.
Ah, stacking. Sweet.
You got cable?
Already wired.
Just call to activate.
High speed, whatever.
Bathroom, cool tile.
Bedroom.
Nice.
I'm a fan of the hardwood.
So you're interested?
Definitely.
Definitely, yeah.
And you're good
with NP, NS?
Uh, sorry. What?
In the ad?
No smoking, no pets.
You wanna smoke,
you do it outside.
Uh, no.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no.
Um, it's cool. No worries.
All right, the usual drill.
I'll need a W-2 or recent
pay stub, current employer,
former address, you know,
the yadda yadda.
And if it's all copacetic,
I'll call.
Yeah. Look, uh,
the thing is,
I can...
Unbelievable.
Look, I'm just currently
in between situations.
Then I'm currently
not renting.
Look, look, I got the money
and I'm totally good for it
for, like, ever.
Come on, yo, can you please,
please just help a brother out?
Yo, my dad's not really
a make-exceptions kind of guy.
Trust me.
Your dad?
Owns the place.
I manage it.
Pen on paper.
That's what I need.
Or go run your game
somewhere else.
Dude, I got nowhere else to go.
This is it.
And I got no game,
all right?
I just need a chance.
[SIGHS]
Look, um, my folks,
they kicked me out.
I'm a disappointment,
apparently.
Didn't meet
their expectations again.
So you know, now I'm persona
non gratis or whatever.
But you know what? I'm a good
person, and I work hard.
I will pay you every month
and I will pay you on time.
I will not mess this up, okay?
I swear.
[SIGHS]
Rent just went up.
A hundred more a month.
That's the cash price.
Yes.
Okay. Yes.
Hey, you rock.
Thank you. Thank you.
You won't regret this.
And in addition
to first and last,
I want two more months.
DBAA fee, nonrefundable.
Yeah, of course. No problem.
DBAA. Obviously, yeah.
All right.
So, what's--? What's DBAA?
Don't be an asshole.
Gotcha.
I live next door.
Really?
And don't think
for one second
you have squatter's rights.
You don't.
If you blow this,
I want you gone.
I know guys that'll have
your skinny ass
out back by the Dumpster
faster than you can blink.
Wow.
I'll fill it in.
Just sign your name.
Which is what,
by the way?
It's Jesse.
Uh, Jesse Jackson.
Seriously?
What?
[LAUGHS]
HANK:
♪ Here's to good friends ♪
♪ Tonight is kind of special ♪
♪ Beer will pour ♪
[BOTTLES RATTLING]
♪ So tonight ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ A little bit
Of Schraderbrau ♪
♪ Schraderbrau ♪
[HUMMING]
What are you doing?
Beating off.
What's it look like I'm doing?
That is in fact exactly
what it looks like to me.
Brewing is an art form,
Marie.
I think you'd appreciate that
by now.
Christmas, batch of '06?
Come on.
So let me
get this straight.
You call in sick the day after
receiving a long-awaited,
career-boosting promotion,
so you can play Oktoberfest
in your man cave?
I don't get it.
Really, I-- I don't.
Babe, relax.
Please, don't tell me to relax.
Sorry, I forgot.
You know I hate that.
Right.
Dave said
I should express that.
All I'm saying
is everything's fine.
I can take a day.
No big deal.
Now get that sweet ass out
of here so I can concentrate.
[GROWLING]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[HANK GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
JESSE:
Okay, so, what's the plan?
WALT:
The plan is we cook.
JESSE:
Why are we cooking
when we can't even move
what we cook?
Well, how much do you think
you can sell on your own?
Say if I cook during the days,
and you work the nights.
Dude.
What?
Prior to Tuco, that was
your plan, wasn't it?
Now, I understand
it'll be a fraction
of what we brought in before,
but still,
what choice do we have?
First of all,
there's no we.
Okay? You're talking me,
solo,
busting hump
slinging shards.
I got profile now.
Don't you get that?
DEA's up my ass.
No, I'm not exposing myself
to that level of risk
for chump change.
No way.
Then what do you suggest?
I don't think either of us
are eager to jump into bed
with another Tuco.
I got bills, man.
You've got bills?
Rent, yo.
Responsibilities.
I've already lost
more than I've made,
and I am tired of
dicking around out here.
You wanna know
how much I've got left?
After completing
my first round of treatment
and financing the world's
most expensive alibi? Huh?
Zero. Zip. Nothing.
I've got nothing to show
for all of this.
Nothing for my family,
which, as you might remember,
was the whole damn point.
[COUGHING]
But seeing as throwing in
the towel is not an option,
that leaves us with
a total of two choices:
We go into business with
yet another homicidal lunatic,
or you and I start--
You selling
whatever you can.
[CLEARS THROAT]
There's a third way.
And what would that be?
We got to be Tuco.
All right?
Cut out the middleman.
Run our own game.
So you're going to what?
Snort meth off a bowie knife?
Huh? You gonna beat your homeys
to death when they "dis" you?
Look, I know some guys.
All right?
I-- I can create a network.
Look, we control production
and distribution.
That way, we stay off
the front lines
while moving
some serious glass.
I mean, the point here
is to make money, right?
Sky-high stacks.
No.
No? That's not the point?
No, I am not willing
to do that.
Who said anything about you?
I don't vote for this plan.
I'm not comfortable
bringing in unknown entities
into our operation.
Yeah?
Well, you don't get to vote.
I beg your pardon?
This is a partnership,
remember?
I rem-- Oh, I remember.
Yeah, you cook, I sell.
That was the division of labor
when we started all this.
And that's exactly
how we should have kept it.
Because I sure as hell didn't
find myself locked in a trunk
or on my knees
with a gun to my head
before your greedy old ass
came along. All right?
All right, I will admit
to a bit of a learning curve.
Oh!
And perhaps
I was overly ambitious.
In any case, it's not gonna
happen that way anymore.
Yeah,
damn straight.
Know why?
Because we do things
my way this time,
or I walk.
You need me more
than I need you, Walt.
[KNOCKING]
Yo, enter my casa.
Yo, Skinny Pete.
What's up, brother?
What up with it, yo?
Hey, Combo. Good to see you.
Welcome to my humble abode.
Good deal, mover.
Good deal.
Yo, Badge, hey.
Oh, cool crib, man.
Hey, it echoes.
Hello.
Hello. Hello, hello, hello.
[BOTH LAUGH]
All right. Let me give you
the virtual tour, okay?
So plasma is
gonna go right here.
Probably like 50-inch,
you know, wall-mounted.
Plasma rocks it over LCD, yo.
No. They burn in, yo.
Ah.
But the picture's,
like, way sharper.
Blacks are deeper too.
They got 3-D coming out,
like, any day now.
That's what I'm waiting for.
Porn, coz.
Jesus.
You know?
Like 3-D tatas,
like right in your face.
Yeah. So I'm gonna get a couple
of those zero-gravity chairs
for, like, right here, for
your ultimate viewing comfort.
Those are buck.
It's gonna be
pretty much sparse.
You know, very Asiany,
modern stuff.
Feng shui, yo.
I can dig it.
JESSE:
Yeah. I'm thinking, you know,
just a bunch of candles,
you know, one of those little
fountain jobs right here.
It's gonna be chill.
The ladies,
they cream up real nice for,
like, candles and shit.
[LAUGHS]
You are going to score,
big time.
[LAUGHS]
All right, so how about we get,
you know, down to it?
There's some refreshments
over here if you wanna partake.
You got any
other refreshments?
I could kick it.
It's been a while.
Yes, yes. I could totally go
for a loving spoonful.
No, no, no. No bomb, no beer,
no weed, all right?
You smoke it up
on your own time.
We're talking business here.
Okay? So listen up.
This is how it goes.
I front each of you
an ounce.
All right?
You sell it for 2,500.
I keep the two,
you keep the five.
No cutting it.
You sell it as is, all right?
Twenty-five hundred
an ounce?
That's kind of, like,
hopeful, bro.
Yeah, Jesse,
street's maybe 17, 18.
Okay, A,
this is the best shiz ever.
All right? Everybody and their
mother's gonna want a taste.
And second, who else
is selling right now, huh?
It's dry out there,
that's for sure.
Church.
JESSE:
So you point it how you want.
Quarter, half,
teener, whatever.
But I make what I make.
Two large. No exceptions.
Short me, you're out.
Cut it, you're out.
Period.
This is a big opportunity
I am giving you.
Understand?
Badger, what is this?
Uh...
A big opportunity.
Exactly. All right?
This is the ground floor.
Gentlemen,
how far you go is up to you.
So bring out
the product, yo.
No, no, no. Not here,
all right? Not ever.
Blind drop. I will let you know
when and where.
All right?
So, uh, you'll be
hearing from me.
Now, I got mad volume.
So you move it quick,
you move it right,
there is always more.
Okay, DBAA, mofos.
All right?
Apply yourselves.
Hell, yeah. Hell, yeah.
[LAUGHS]
[CAR DOOR SLAMS]
HANK:
Hey, there's the big guy.
WALT JR.: Congratulations.
SKYLER: Hey, Hank.
MARIE:
It's an armpit.
HANK:
It's not an armpit.
MARIE:
Oh, excuse me.
You're right. It's the Paris
of the Southwest.
Please, it's Texas,
for God's sake.
Right on the border
of lawless Mexican hell.
Human heads, they leave.
The cartels, they litter
the place with human heads.
Yeah, well, pretty sure
that's why I'm going there.
MARIE:
It's like a calling card
or a shoutout or something.
Now, D.C., on the other hand,
I could get behind.
You just do your time
like a good boy,
and I could see us in a cute
little condo in Georgetown
in a couple of years.
I went online
to this fantastic
real estate website
for D.C.
There's just so much,
I don't know,
culture there.
You know?
I was talking to Melinda,
Hank's boss's wife.
I told you about her,
the one with the helmet hair
and the permanent lip liner.
She was saying that
when they were there--
Shh, shh.
Apologize.
What?
I will not listen
to one more word
until you apologize.
For?
You know perfectly well,
Marie.
Well, obviously I don't--
Your lies.
To me.
The shoplifting.
All of it.
I mean,
did you really think
it was all just neatly
gonna go away?
Well, if you hadn't tried
to return it--
Apologize.
Now or never. I mean it.
Or it'll never
be the same.
Why are you punishing me?
If you don't respect me
enough to apologize,
to tell me the truth, then--
[SIGHS]
I need my sister back.
I'm sorry.
[SNIFFLING]
[CRYING]
HANK:
What do you want,
the gory details?
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
No, you don't.
Keep you up at night.
Uh, so it--
Was it scary?
[SCOFFS]
Hell, yeah, it was freaking
scary, you little punk.
Jesus.
WALT JR.:
But you were way faster
than him.
Well, I'm here,
aren't I?
WALT JR.:
Yeah. Hell, yeah.
Kick ass
and take names.
Son.
HANK: No, it's fine.
You know what it is?
A cockroach comes out
from under a fridge,
what do you do?
I mean,
you don't think about it.
You stomp them down.
Where do they come from?
Criminals,
like the one you, uh...
I mean, what do you think it is
that makes them who they are?
[SCOFFS]
Buddy, you might as well be
asking me about the roaches.
All I know is there's a whole
world of them out there.
Man, I gotta piss
like a racehorse.
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
♪ Yeah ♪
Cops.
Cops!
[LAUGHING]
Wasn't sure it was you.
New car?
Yeah, keeping things on the DL.
I'm guessing
this one doesn't bounce.
Your half.
Fifteen K.
That's what I'm talking about.
Uh, you're welcome.
Jesus.
Help me understand
the math, okay?
I gave you 1 pound,
correct?
You and I split
$2,000 per ounce.
One thousand dollars each.
One pound,
that's 16 ounces.
Sixteen ounces
should net to me $16,000.
Sixteen. Not 15.
Something came up.
Something came up?
One of my guys got held up
by a couple junkies.
Lost an ounce.
But it's cool, okay?
Skinny Pete's cool.
[LAUGHS]
Oh.
So you're saying
that your guy got robbed--
Or rather you got robbed.
--but it doesn't matter.
Hm?
Dude, it's called breakage,
okay?
Like Kmart. Shit breaks.
And you're thinking
this is acceptable?
It's the cost
of business, yo.
You're sweating me
over a grand?
Hey, look,
I'm just the chemist here.
I'm not the street guy, yo.
But it seems to me that
what you call breakage
is just you making
a fool of yourself.
I've got another
technical term for you.
Non-sustainable
business model.
You're focusing
on the negative.
Six grand a day we're making.
What's your problem?
What happens when
word gets out,
and it's open season on these
clowns you've hired, hm?
Once everyone knows
that Jesse Pinkman,
drug lord, can be robbed
with impunity.
Man, come on.
You think Tuco had breakage?
I guess it's true, he did.
He broke bones.
He broke the skull of anybody
who tried to rip him off.
You want another grand?
Is that it?
That's not my point.
Take it. Here.
Look, you got 15,000
you didn't have yesterday.
Hey, we're making bank.
Shit happens.
My guys get what they're
up against, and they're careful.
So am I.
And you're all tucked in at
night with your precious family.
So why don't you just stop being
such a freak about everything?
You've made the division
of labor very clear.
Yo, I mean, seriously,
what the hell
do you want me to do, huh?
[MICROWAVE WHIRRING]
[MICROWAVE BEEPING]
WALT: Hey.
SKYLER: Huh? Oh.
WALT:
Sorry.
SKYLER:
Wow, you snuck in.
Didn't even know
you were home.
[SIGHS]
What you eating?
A panini.
There's another one
in the freezer if you want it.
Honey, I thought
we nixed those, huh?
Did we?
Yeah. I mean,
aren't those the ones
with the off-the-chart
sodium?
I had a craving.
Once in a while
is no big deal.
So where's Jr.?
Out.
With whom?
Louis.
Out where?
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Somewhere. I don't know.
Huh.
He'll be back by 9.
Okay.
Yeah, I just thought you might
have a clue where your son is.
Why don't you?
Why am I the only one who needs
to keep track of our son?
I'll tell you what, Walt.
You wanna know where he is,
ask him.
Just pick up the phone
like I do.
[SIGHS]
Great.
Perhaps you might know
something
about this.
Perhaps.
Mm-hm.
And then again,
perhaps I don't, Walt.
Perhaps I smoked them
in a fugue state.
I'd like an explanation,
please.
Oh, you don't wanna go down
that road.
Why would you do this?
You're pregnant,
for God's sakes.
Three and a half cigarettes
is not gonna do a thing
to the baby.
Oh, okay, well,
I'm glad you're so sure, doctor.
Three and a half.
That was it. I tossed the rest.
And I'm sure
you'll be very glad to hear
that, yes, I feel ashamed.
Skyler, this--
I mean,
this is something that--
This is so unlike you. Why--?
Oh, really?
How would you know?
[GRUNTS]
No, thank you.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[GUNSHOT]
[GUNSHOT, GLASS BREAKS]
Hank.
[GUNSHOTS, GLASS BREAKS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GUNSHOT, GLASS BREAKS]
[DOOR OPENS]
Jesus.
[MARIE SCREAMS]
[BRAKES SQUEAL]
[IGNITION SHUTS OFF]
Yo.
[DOOR CLOSES]
You asked me what
I want you to do.
I want you to handle it.
[♪♪♪]