Hey.
You, um...
You selling?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Okay. That's cool.
I'm just saying, you know,
if you were selling,
I could maybe do with
a teenth.
You're kidding, right?
Dude,
I so smell bacon.
What? What are you
talking about?
Oh, gee,
I don't know.
How about over there.
That brown van.
That's yours, right?
What brown van?
Parked all
inconspicuous.
It's a cop van.
Yeah, another one
right over there.
"Duke City Flowers"?
Come on.
Can't you at least
be original?
Dude,
I just wanna get high.
A flower van.
[SIGHS]
You know what you should do
is a garbage truck.
Seriously, and I don't
mean to disrespect,
but if you put a bunch of cops
in the back of a garbage truck,
there's no way
I'm seriously thinking
that there's cops in the
back of a garbage truck.
It's a freebie, yo.
Just think about it.
Think about it, boys.
[LAUGHS]
All right.
I'm hitting it.
Oh. You dudes
give up that easy?
I'm not a cop.
Then lift your shirt. Show me
you're not wearing a wire.
All right, you know what?
Just to show you
you're being an asshole.
Ah! I'm blinded by white.
Ha-ha-ha.
Douchebag.
Ah, come on.
I was joking. Come on.
Don't walk away angry.
Sit down. Come on.
I mean, w-what are you
complaining about?
You got abs, man.
Kind of.
Whatever, dude.
I'm not even sure
I wanna buy anymore.
I think you turned me off
to the whole thing.
Come on.
Don't be like that.
I just-- I just need you
to prove it, you know?
Prove you're not
a cop.
How the hell
am I supposed to do that?
I don't know.
Hey, I got it.
Go over there and punch
that dude right in the face.
Which dude?
That dude?
Yeah.
No way.
He'd kick my ass.
[LAUGHS]
True that.
Argh!
This is so hard,
you know?
Yeah.
I know.
It's simple.
If you ask a cop if he's a cop,
he's, like,
obligated to tell you.
It's in the Constitution.
Constitution of America?
Huh.
So-- So go ahead and ask.
You a cop?
No, no. Not like that.
Ask it, like, official.
Are you
a police officer?
No,
I am not a police officer.
Okay, then. Hundred
and seventy-five for a teenth.
Whoa.
The price is the price, yo.
All right.
There you go. Enjoy.
Thanks, man.
Albuquerque Police! You're
under arrest! Get on the ground!
[POLICE SIREN WAILING]
Get on your stomach now!
On your stomach.
Get on the ground!
OFFICER:
Hold it right there.
Don't move. Stay down.
[♪♪♪]
I had a good job until my boss
accused me of stealing.
I'd better call Saul!
I was out partying,
minding my own business
You are under arrest.
I'd better call Saul!
Hi. I'm Saul Goodman.
Did you know
that you have rights?
The Constitution says you do.
And so do I.
I believe
that until proven guilty,
every man, woman, and child
in this country is innocent.
And that's why I fight for you,
Albuquerque.
ANNOUNCER:
Better call Saul.
Saul Goodman, attorney at law,
505-164-CALL.
That's 505-164-CALL.
JESSE:
I, uh, really need to get
some furniture.
I suggest you start
with a bed.
[JESSE CHUCKLES]
JESSE:
God, I wish
we could smoke in here.
Well, you can't.
Yeah, no. I know.
I'm just saying.
Don't think I can't
smell that weed.
You better seriously hope
that airs out.
My dad will keep
your security deposit.
He has a nose
like a damn bloodhound.
[LAUGHS]
Yeah?
Has he, um,
ever caught you?
Oh. Yeah.
Many times.
Well, listen. Um...
Since I already lost
my deposit and all,
maybe we should light up.
No, thanks.
You sure?
Well, is it cool
if I burn one?
Maybe you'll change
your mind.
Do what you wanna do,
I guess.
Whoa.
Hey. What'd I say?
Nothing.
I just have to go is all.
What's this?
My 18-month chip.
I'm in recovery.
And, you know,
pot is like stepping stones.
Recovery? That's-- That's cool.
Right on.
I respect that.
You know, I don't really
burn much anymore.
It's just a sometime thing.
But no more, like,
in the house.
So, um, you wanna go grab
some-- Some dinner?
I could really go
for some Chinese.
No, I better hit it.
We, um...
We cool?
[INDISTINCT SOUNDS ON TV]
Your satellite is on,
by the way.
That screen is badass.
[SIGHS]
WALT:
I just think it's asking a lot.
SKYLER:
He knows it.
He's done nothing
but apologize.
Is this gonna be
every weekend now?
No. It's just the end
of the quarter.
You remember how that was.
But I am earning double time,
so there's a bright side.
So when the laziest boy
in the world wakes up,
tell him he better wash
those sneakers.
And I said bye.
Ooh, and tell him
to let them air-dry this time.
I don't want him banging
the hell out of my dryer.
What?
What, you don't even get
casual Saturday?
I mean...
No, it's just you--
You look nice is all.
It's work, Walt.
And everybody is gonna be there.
Okay.
Maybe we'll order
a pizza tonight?
Okay.
Bye.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[PHONE RINGING]
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hi. You've reached Walt,
Skyler and Walter, Jr.
Please leave a message,
and we'll get back to you.
MARIE:
Skyler? Are you there?
I don't know what to do.
I-- I need to talk to you. I--
Hey, Marie. It's me.
What's up?
Yesterday I got home
and found him.
He didn't even tell me
he was coming.
A man was killed?
A Federale,
right in front of him.
Three agents wounded,
one lost his leg.
It's like what you hear about
from Iraq or something.
The IEDs.
Oh, Jesus.
I had to hear about it
from Steve Gomez.
Hank talked to his ASAC
for about an hour.
Hank could win an Oscar. He's
so damn breezy with the man.
He hangs up the phone,
goes right back to bed.
And all he keeps saying is,
"I'm fine. I'm fine.
Leave me alone."
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Baby, not now.
WALT:
Uh, it's-- It's me, Hank.
Sorry. I--
Hey, buddy. What's--?
What's up?
Um, I just--
Do you mind if I...?
No, no.
So, uh...
How you doing?
Oh, you know, lousy.
Montezuma's revenge,
bigtime.
I mean,
everything's going through me
like, uh,
crap through a tinhorn.
[CHUCKLES]
Better not get
too close.
Well,
I'll take my chances.
I guess y-you heard about
what happened down in Juárez?
Terrible.
What do you expect?
Bunch of freaking animals.
It's like Apocalypse Now
down there.
It's like Colonel Kurtz
holed up in his jungle.
And my SAC in El Paso
sends me home.
Now, that's a sound leadership
decision right there, huh?
You know, y-you don't put
your second most senior man
on the trail
of those motherless bastards,
you send him home.
You know? Ahem.
I was, you know-- "He's out
getting an evidence bag
"and so ends up
without a scratch on him.
So must be something wrong
with that picture, you know."
So are you home
for good then?
Uh...
No, no. It's, uh...
Playing it by ear.
To be determined.
Think you might wanna
talk it through with somebody?
What, a shrink? No, no, no.
Can't go down that road.
Start going down that road,
kiss your career goodbye.
Or Marie.
Or me, if-- If you like.
You know, um, I don't know
how to say this. I, uh...
You know,
the things I deal with,
you and me don't have
much of a--
What you might call
"an experiential overlap."
What if I told you we do?
I have spent
my whole life scared.
Frightened of things
that could happen,
might happen,
might not happen.
Fifty years I spent like that.
Finding myself awake
at 3 in the morning.
But you know what?
Ever since my diagnosis...
I sleep just fine.
Okay.
And I came to realize
it's that fear
that's the worst of it.
That's the real enemy.
So...
Get up.
Get out in the real world.
And you kick that bastard
as hard as you can
right in the teeth.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
Do it again. Go on.
Ten thousand even, same as last
time. It's totally accurate.
You and I, we are
gonna feed this machine.
I want it running
24 hours a day.
Right on.
Not yours, I take it.
We got 10,
20, 30,
44,
five each.
Three pounds
should be 48 each.
Who's short?
All right. Don't freak, all
right? We didn't get ripped off.
But Badger hasn't kicked in
his full amount.
I know he was planning on
pulling an all-nighter,
so he's probably
still in the sack.
Then wake him up.
He can sleep
after we're paid.
Why you gotta be such
a hard-on?
You're not his pal.
You're his boss.
This only works when
they're scared of you, remember?
[MUMBLES]
Jack-off.
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Leave a message--
It's going straight
to voicemail.
Voicemail? Oh.
Just chill, okay?
Count your money.
Combo.
COMBO: Yo, what's up?
You seen Badger?
Yo, don't you cover
for him, bitch.
I ask you a straight-up
question,
I expect a straight-up answer.
Well?
They were too scared
to tell me.
Badger got busted.
He's in jail.
[♪♪♪]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
HANK:
Honey, I'm home!
Oh! Too slow! What's up?
Got more lives than
a damn cat.
Now if I could only learn
to lick myself.
[LAUGHS]
What's up, guys?
Good to see you.
All right. Let's all get back
to work, for chrissake, okay?
In my office, man.
Let's see what you bozos
been up to lately.
You okay?
Hanging in?
What's it look like?
What's this from A.P.D.?
Been checking with them to see
if they come across
that famous blue meth of yours.
Sure enough, last night.
Got themselves
an honest-to-God dealer.
I was thinking of cruising over
and saying hello.
Maybe you'd like
to go with me?
Yeah. Well, all right.
BADGER:
You told me to my face
you weren't a cop, man.
I feel manipulated.
I thought we were
gonna hang out.
GETZ:
We are hanging out, Badger.
You like Badger
or Brandon?
I like people who don't,
like,
abuse the Constitution.
Badger, listen.
Hey.
I'm trying to
help you here, man.
Now, if you just tell me
who your supplier is,
I think this can end
very well for you.
Eh! What are you doing,
detective?
What are you doing talking
to my client without me present?
You sneaky Pete.
Which is which?
What, did the academy hire you
right out of the womb?
You guys
get younger every--
What'd you say
to baby face, huh?
Huh? Did you say
anything stupid?
By "anything stupid,"
I mean anything at all.
Look at you. Mouth open,
vocal chords a-twitter.
We'll talk about it later.
Right now, you out.
Ten minutes ago. Go on.
There are laws, detective.
Have your kindergarten teacher
read them to you.
Go grab a juice box.
Have a nap. Go on.
[LAUGHS]
All right.
Who do we have?
Brandon Mayhew.
Brandon Mayhew. All right.
Here we go. Public masturbation.
What?
I don't get it.
What's the kick?
Why don't you do it at home
like the rest of us
with a big flat-screen TV,
50 channels of pay-per-view?
In a Starbucks.
That's nice. Ha-ha.
That ain't me, man. I--
I was the guy who was
selling meth.
Allegedly.
Okay. All right. I got you.
Meth. Right.
Sorry, that was a little
transpositional error.
Nothing a little Wite-Out
can't take care of.
Yeah, and, uh,
felony quantity.
Just barely.
Yeah, just barely.
The cops here
are like butchers.
Always got their thumbs
on the scales.
But good luck
arguing that in court.
[LAUGHS]
Let me get down
to brass tacks.
I'm gonna get you
a second phone call.
Okay, you're gonna call
your mommy or your daddy
or your parish priest
or your Boy Scout leader,
and they're gonna
deliver me a check for $4650.
I'm gonna write that down
on the back of my business card.
Okay. Four-six-five-zero.
Okay?
And I need that in a cashier's
check or a money order,
doesn't matter.
Actually, uh,
I want it in a money order.
And, uh, make it out to
"Ice Station Zebra Associates."
That's my loan-out.
It's, uh, totally legit.
It's done
just for tax purposes.
And after that, we can discuss
Visa or MasterCard,
but definitely not
American Express,
so don't even ask. All right?
Any questions?
Uh-- You're gonna
get me off, right?
Uh, what do I look like,
your high-school girlfriend?
Five fingers, no waiting?
That's a joke, Brandon.
Lighten up.
Son, I promise you this.
I will give you
the best criminal defense
that money can buy.
Yeah, but, Francesca,
I took these already.
Didn't I take these already?
Okay.
Look, it's on your head.
You're not supposed to
double up on vitamin A.
It's bad for the liver.
Okay, who's next?
Did him. I did him.
That one went public defender.
Thanks for nothing.
Hey, what happened
to my masturbator, Francesca?
You got me all turned around.
Hang on.
I'll get back to you.
Gentlemen, I sense
you're discussing my client.
Anything you care
to share with me?
Sure. Your commercials?
They suck ass.
I've seen better acting
in an epileptic whorehouse.
Is that like the one
your mom works at?
Is she still offering
the two-for-one discount?
DEA, huh? For a street bust.
Now, what would two feds
want with that little twerp?
JESSE:
Sooner or later,
this was gonna happen.
You want your
exponential growth,
guys are gonna get busted.
Simple as that.
How about we get him a real
attorney? What the hell is this?
This is who he hires?
What? Are you kidding me?
This is the guy you want.
This is the guy I'd hire.
Oh, it's the guy you'd hire.
Look,
you remember Emilio?
Okay, this dude got Emilio off,
like, twice. Okay?
Both times, they had him
dead to rights, yo.
And then, poof.
Dude is like Houdini.
Seriously,
when the going gets tough,
you don't want
a criminal lawyer.
You want a "criminal" lawyer.
Know what I'm saying?
Look, we're in good shape,
Mr. White.
Badger is way too loyal
to roll.
Plus, he's scared
shitless of me, all right.
We pay four large.
Cost of business.
Take it out of his payroll.
And it's only
his first dealing rap,
so, worst-case scenario,
you know, they plead him out.
He does five months picking up
litter in an orange jump suit.
So who goes inside? I don't
need them seeing my face.
Well, I don't need them
seeing my face.
Why not? You look like
his typical clientele.
Dick.
Fine.
We'll flip for it, all right?
Call it.
Heads.
[BABY CRYING]
["AMERICA THE BEAUTIFUL"
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
WOMAN [ON PA]:
Mayhew? Mr. Mayhew?
[BABY CRYING]
Mr., uh, Mayhew.
Nice of you to come down.
Please.
Oh, look at you.
Should I call the FBI and tell
them I found D.B. Cooper?
[LAUGHS]
Joking.
I-- Please, come on.
Come on. Please.
Hello.
Saul Goodman. Please sit.
So it's a shame
that we have to meet
under these circumstances.
I believe you have
something for me?
Oh, yes.
Mayhew.
Is that, uh, Irish or English?
Uh, Irish.
[IN IRISH ACCENT]
Faith and begorra.
A fellow potato-eater.
My real name is McGill.
The Jew thing
I just do for the homeboys.
They all want a pipe-hitting
member of the tribe,
so to speak.
I digress.
Um, good things are happening.
Fact is, your nephew is gonna
get out in no time.
That's wonderful, yeah.
There's still a few details
to be ironed out,
but now that the DEA
is involved,
I think he's looking
at time served, then probation.
So leave your number
with Francesca,
and, uh, we'll be in touch.
Excuse me, the DEA?
Yeah.
That's the Drug Enforcement
Administration. The feds.
I hope that I'm not
the breaker of bad news,
but your nephew got mixed up
with some pretty nasty
customers.
I understand that.
But what does that
have to do with the DEA?
They're after
some mystery man,
some heavy-hitter who
goes by the name Heisenberg.
They want this guy
like the ax wants the turkey.
Seems young Brandon
may have some information
that could lead
to his arrest.
Jesus, cheer up.
This is good news.
I mean, Brandon fell head-first
into the doo-doo pile
and came up smelling
like Paco Rabanne. Ha-ha.
Wait, wait. Look, I just--
I think--
I-I just think that we should
review our options.
Options?
I'm gonna tell you
what your options are, okay.
You got a grand total of two.
Option A:
Brandon takes the deal.
Option B: Brandon goes up
to the penitentiary
and gets his rectum
resized about yay big.
Look, look. What--?
What about reprisals?
I mean, if-- If Badger--
If Brandon informs
on this Heisenberg,
I mean, what if, God forbid,
that they decide to...
take revenge?
What have you
been telling him?
The kid keeps
spouting off about,
"If I talk, they'll kill me."
Blah, blah, blah.
Right now, he's the only thing
holding up this deal.
Good.
No, that's not good.
That's terrible.
Trust me, sir,
your nephew won't last
in prison two weeks.
You let him take his chances
on the outside.
Maybe I can work
in some witness protection.
No, look, look. These are
vicious, desperate people.
I-I-- I've been told that
one of them killed another man
by crushing his head
with an ATM machine.
Ha-ha. People love to take
credit for the fun ones.
The guy who got
his head smooshed
used to be a client of mine.
His wife killed him, all right?
It was open and shut.
Trust me, you folks have
nothing to worry about, okay?
I'm gonna set your
nephew straight,
get him singing
like a canary,
all's right with the world.
Ten thousand dollars.
[COUGHING]
Ten thousand, cash to you.
I'm not saying
to throw the case.
Just no talking
to the DEA.
Are you saying
what I think you're saying?
Yes.
What's it going to be?
JESSE:
What, dude wouldn't
take a bribe?
That dude in there? Saul Goodman
we're talking about?
Yeah. "Morally outraged,"
he said.
Threatened to call
the police.
Wait,
and Badger is gonna spill?
Like the Exxon Valdez.
So,
what do we do about it?
SAUL:
Hey, Francesca,
how about I follow you home?
FRANCESCA:
No.
SAUL:
For safety.
What?
God, you are killing me
with that booty.
[GRUNTS]
[CAR ALARM CHIRPS]
SAUL:
Talk to me. Come on,
talk to me, guys, huh?
Come on, just tell me
what you want. Jesus!
Oh! Oh, no, no, no!
No, it wasn't me.
It was Ignacio. He's the one.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no.
[SAUL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
JESSE:
Shut up, dude.
Shut up, all right?
Just speak English.
Lalo didn't send you?
No Lalo?
Who?
Oh, thank God! Oh, Christ!
Oh, I thought...
What can I do
for you gentlemen?
Anything. Just tell me wh--
What you need.
JESSE:
This afternoon, an associate
of ours offered you $10,000.
You should have taken it.
Wait a minute. This-- This is in
regards to-- To what's-his-name?
Badger! Brandon Mayhew.
The uncle. The uncle,
that was your guy?
Heh. No offense, guys,
but I-I don't take bribes
from strangers, you know?
Better safe than sorry.
That's my motto.
But I'll take your money!
Sure!
No,
that offer has expired, yo.
It was kind of low anyways.
But okay, okay, I-I'll take it.
Just tell me what
you need, all right?
I'm easy. I'm gonna keep
a happy thought
and assume this is just
a negotiating tactic.
All right, listen to me
very carefully.
You are going to give
Badger Mayhew
the best legal
representation ever.
But no deals
with the DEA.
All right? Badger will not
identify anyone to anybody.
If he does, you're dead.
Why don't you just kill Badger?
I mean, follow me, guys. But if
a mosquito is buzzing around you
and it bites you on the ass,
you don't go gunning for
the mosquito's attorney.
You go grab a fly swatter.
I mean, so to speak.
I mean,
all due respect,
but do I have to spell this
out for you?
We're not killing Badger, yo.
Then you got real problems,
okay.
Because the DEA
is gonna come down on your boy
like a proverbial ton of bricks.
I mean, I don't think
I'm going out on a limb here,
but, hey,
he's not gonna like prison.
He's gonna sing like Celine Dion
regardless of what you do to me.
[COUGHING]
Mr. Mayhew?
I recognize your cough.
Take that mask off, you know.
Get some air.
Go on.
Ugh! God.
Take it easy.
Breathe in,
breathe out.
All right. I'm gonna stand up,
all right?
Because I got bad knees.
That's better.
Okay, n-now listen. The three
of us are gonna work this out.
Yeah? How?
First thing, you'll put a dollar
in my pocket, both of you.
You want attorney-client
privilege, don't you?
So that everything you say
is strictly between us.
I mean it.
Put a dollar in my pocket.
Come on, make it official.
Come on, do it.
That's it, come on.
Just a dollar.
All right, now you, ski bum.
Come on. Give with the dollar.
Go on.
Be smart.
What?
All I got is a five.
I'll take a five.
Come on, already.
Come on. Be cool.
Okay, you're now both
officially represented
by Saul Goodman
and Associates.
Your secrets are safe with me
under threat of disbarment,
all right?
Take the ski mask off.
I feel like I'm talking
to the Weather Underground here.
Just do it.
[COUGHING]
Okay, so if a prison shanking
is completely off the table--
And we're sure of that?
No shanking!
[GROANS]
All right, all right.
The way I see it is
somebody is going to prison.
It's just a matter of who.
HANK:
All right.
Lame-ass TV ads aside,
your, uh, lawyer here,
he cooked you up
a pretty killer deal.
Time served, no probation.
It's pretty slick. Couldn't
believe the judge went for it.
[LAUGHS]
Don't get cocky. You ain't--
You ain't home free yet.
You don't give us
the name of your supplier,
you're going nowhere.
Agent, the, uh,
tough guy act is unnecessary.
This young man
is cooperating fully.
Is that right?
Yeah, you cooperating?
Okay,
let's start with a name.
He just goes by Heisenberg.
Heisenberg, huh?
How old is this Heisenberg?
Old. Like 50 or 70
or something.
Height?
Average, I guess.
Medium height,
medium weight.
What color hair?
No hair.
Dude's balder than you.
SAUL:
1963, James Edward Kilkelly
is convicted of stealing
a vending machine.
1975, breaking and entering.
1982, grand theft auto.
1984, armed robbery.
1987, 1992. You get the idea.
And here he is today.
Better known as
Jimmy In-'N-Out.
City, state and federal,
he's spent 44 of the last
58 years inside.
Entire life behind bars.
SAUL:
Jimmy provides
a very special service.
For a price,
Jimmy will go to prison for you.
On purpose? The guy goes
to prison on purpose?
He's actually
more comfortable inside.
The outside world
hasn't been too kind to him.
Sometime during
the Clinton administration,
Jimmy figured out how he could
use his talents
to turn a profit.
So when does
all this happen?
It's already happening.
The buy is set
for tomorrow.
Cops bust Jimmy, Badger
gets out, everybody's happy,
and all it's gonna cost you
is 80 thousand and one pound
of your finest meth.
Eighty thousand dollars for
eight years of his life, huh?
SAUL:
First of all,
he's not gonna do eight years.
I'll represent him,
and I guarantee
there's gonna be
some unexpected problems
with the prosecution's case.
Secondly, he gets 30.
Fifty goes to me.
You get 50? For what?
For facilitating.
Who's taking a bigger risk here?
He likes prison.
You did bring the cash,
didn't you?
Look, if this option
is too expensive, uh,
you can still always, ugh,
Badger in the chow line.
Conscience gets expensive,
doesn't it?
GETZ:
All right. There's our boy.
Right on time.
Whoa, whoa. Go back.
What? All right,
all right, all right.
[♪♪♪]
WALT:
So, what do you think?
They see us?
JESSE:
Uh, no, man, I think we're good.
Badger looks like
he's gonna throw up.
WALT:
Give me those back.
Just give them to me.
Oh, no.
Where the hell is Jimmy?
Should've been here
10 minutes ago.
You think Jimmy
is actually for real?
A guy who wants
to be in prison?
There's more
than one kind of prison.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
WALT:
There he is--
Wait a minute.
Oh, no, no, no.
What? What? Let me see.
Who the hell is that?
I don't know.
GETZ:
Mr. Heisenberg, I presume.
Time to move?
Not till we see the exchange.
No, no. Oh, shit.
What?
Now he shows.
Okay, let's do this.
JESSE:
No, no.
Oh, my God. Jimmy is
on the wrong bench. Crap!
We are screwed!
Uh, what are you doing?
Hey, uh, what are you doing?
GOMEZ:
I don't get it.
What's the holdup?
Where's the stuff, man?
Where are we going?
Just shut up.
Get out. Go stop him.
The DEA is right there.
If they see me, we're screwed.
Get out. I'll do something.
What?
Just go!
Hank, I thought that was you.
Schrader, I'm blocked.
Walt, not a good time.
How you doing? You feeling okay?
Schrader, I'm blocked.
We're working.
You gotta get out of here.
Working? Oh, like DEA working?
Schrader, we're missing it.
Is something going down?
[WHISPERING]
Wrong guy, wrong guy.
Other bench.
HANK:
Walt, Walt.
Walter, move your ass now.
Okay.
Listen, I-I'll just go,
and leave you alone.
We'll talk about it later.
Just floor it.
Should I back up? Or--?
No. Go that way.
Forward is better?
I'll be out of the way there.
Okay, okay.
Floor it!
I'm sorry, all right? I'm sorry.
I'll leave you alone.
We'll talk later. Just go.
Where'd he go?
Where the hell did he go?
Oh, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Got him.
Looks like it's going down.
HANK: Take him.
[POLICE SIREN WAILING]
COP 1:
Freeze! Hey, right there.
Don't move.
Come on, let's get him up.
Ugh!
Jesus!
I think they bought it.
GETZ:
Absolutely.
Textbook bust, sir. Yes, sir.
Looks like we got a full pound
of the blue stuff.
Oh, and Heisenberg's real name?
James Kilkelly.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
It was my pleasure.
[KNOCKING]
Hey.
You weren't home,
so I let the delivery guys in.
I hope that's okay.
Absolutely.
So you bought a bed.
Yeah.
What is that,
a king?
Uh-huh.
Pillow top?
[WALT COUGHING]
Oh, my God.
You really are
a chemistry teacher.
[CHUCKLES]
Uh...
You mind?
I was terrible at chemistry.
I'm, uh, more of
a humanities guy.
How did you find me?
We should talk about that.
It should be much,
much harder
for people to track you down.
My PI charged me
for three hours.
so I seriously doubt
it took him more than one.
So this is, what,
blackmail?
Walter, I'm your lawyer.
Anything you say to me
is totally privileged.
I'm not in the shakedown racket.
I'm a lawyer. Even drug dealers
need lawyers, right?
Especially drug dealers.
So, what,
you're just doing this
out of the kindness
of your heart?
Come on. Have you
seen my hourly rate?
[LAUGHS]
By the way,
where do you keep the money?
Is it in your mattress?
Is it in a jelly jar
buried in the side yard, huh?
This kid Mayhew may be the first
of your guys to get picked up,
but he won't be the last.
And if I can find you,
how far behind
can the cops be?
I don't understand.
What exactly are you
offering to do for me?
What did Tom Hagen
do for Vito Corleone?
I-I'm no Vito Corleone.
No shit.
Right now, you're Fredo.
But, you know,
with some sound advice
and the proper introductions,
who knows?
I'll tell you one thing,
you've got the right product.
Anything that gets the DEA's
panties in this big a bunch,
you're on to something special.
And I would like to be
a small and silent part of it.
Food for thought, yeah?
So if you wanna make
more money
and, uh, keep the money
that you make...
better call Saul!
[LAUGHS]
[COUGHING]
[♪♪♪]