MARIE:
Ugh, these people.
Pathetic.
I already read that one
anyway.
Kleinman has better
magazines.
You know, y-you guys really
don't need to hang around.
We won't even get the results
till next week.
Buddy, w-we're gonna be here.
You kidding me?
It is a full PET/CT,
correct?
You definitely want the PET/CT
and not just the PET.
Yeah, it's a--
It's a PET/CT.
Good.
That's what you want.
Some places skimp
and they only do the PET.
I'm not naming any names.
I just still don't understand
why you don't go to Kleinman.
This is where
Walt's doctor is.
Well, with us, you wouldn't
have to wait until next week
to get the results.
I'm sorry, but these scans
are not that difficult to read.
I could take one look at Walt's
and tell you immediately
how he's doing.
Really.
Doctors like people to think
that they're so much smarter
than the technicians,
but you would be surprised how
much they come to us for input.
[COUGHS]
Well, never turn down a chance
to hit the bathroom, huh?
Excuse me.
[COUGHING]
You all right
in there?
Uh, yeah.
[COUGHING]
MAN:
Hey, you okay?
Yes.
I'm fine, thank you.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[MACHINE HUMMING]
MAN:
Sir, you can go back to your
changing room and get dressed.
So, uh, how'd we do?
You did fine.
See anything?
I'm just a technician,
Mr. White.
Dr. Delcavoli will go over
the results with you next week.
Sorry.
Ah.
[♪♪♪]
SAUL:
Actually,
the money-laundering aspect
is fairly straightforward.
But I gotta tell you, the
not-telling-your-wife aspect?
Most people wanna know
why they suddenly got rich.
If she finds out,
it's after I'm gone.
How much time they giving you?
Weeks.
Maybe.
Hm. Sorry to hear it.
I was, uh, hoping we could
make some real money together.
Oh, well.
Look, let's crunch some numbers.
How much money
are we laundering?
At this time, $16,000.
How long you been doing this?
We've had some
extenuating circumstances.
Yeah, apparently.
All right, 16,000 laundered
at 75 cents on the dollar,
minus my fee,
which is 17 percent,
comes to $9960.
Congratulations, you just left
your family a secondhand Subaru.
Well, we'll just have
to cook more. A lot more.
Yeah, that's, uh,
that's my legal opinion.
Make hay while the sun
is still shining.
[COUGHING]
SKYLER:
You know, we should do something
this weekend.
You know, get our minds
off the test results.
Actually, I, uh...
I'm thinking
I should go see Mom.
[SIGHS]
Really?
Yeah.
You know, I never did call her.
You're expecting the--
The news from the scan
to be bad.
God, Walt.
I need you to stay positive
with me here.
I am. Positive is good.
I'm all for positive,
but positive doesn't
change facts, all right?
It-- It--
It doesn't change the need
to be prepared.
I know.
Walt, I'm just
trying to be hopeful, okay?
You know, forgive me.
Look,
I need to know Mom's going
to leave you something if--
If...
I'm no longer around.
I just need to get that
straight, that's all.
And believe me, I'm gonna
earn every penny of it too.
Complaining about her nurses
the entire time.
"Juanita is hiding
my ashtray."
[BOTH LAUGH]
A 30-minute discourse
about how the sugar packets
are suddenly disappearing.
And, oh, she's counting
every one of them, you know.
[COUGHING]
I'll be lucky
if I get a word in edgewise.
I actually think the news from
the scan is gonna be good.
Perhaps you should
prepare for that.
Yeah.
[JANE GIGGLING]
We should do something.
Yeah, we should.
No, something else.
[GROANS]
We should go somewhere.
Have you been
to the Georgia O'Keeffe Museum?
Is that the, uh,
one with the A-bombs?
Georgia O'Keeffe.
She's a painter.
You've never heard
of Georgia O'Keeffe?
No, is that bad?
Boy,
you need some educating.
Yes, yes, I do.
Come here.
Why don't we go up to Santa Fe?
We'll make a day of it.
You wanna go all the way
to Santa Fe for a museum?
So romantic.
Yup, we're going. Get up.
Oh. Why can't we just go
to the movies or putt-putt?
It's the shit.
A little culture
won't kill you.
Besides, you might like it.
A lot of her paintings
look like vaginas.
Ooh. Really?
Is there still cereal?
Yeah.
[PHONE RINGING]
JESSE [ON RECORDING]:
Yo, if I know you,
leave a message.
WALT:
Where the hell are you?
Pick up the phone.
Hello? Jesse, pick up--
Hold on, hold on.
Sorry, one sec.
What?
I've been trying to reach you.
Where's your drop phone?
Oh. Uh, I've been busy.
Well,
clear your social calendar.
We have to cook.
What? Today?
No, you'll need today at least
to gather supplies.
Now, we're going to need
all new glassware,
heating mantles,
about a hundred pounds of ice.
Do you have a paper and pencil?
You should be writing this down.
You wanna go shopping,
go do it yourself, all right?
I got plans.
Smoking marijuana, eating
Cheetos, and masturbating
do not constitute plans
in my book.
Well, screw you and your book,
man, all right?
I'm going to a museum in Santa
Fe, not like you need to know.
You're going to a museum, huh?
Yeah. Georgia O'Keeffe.
Georgia O'Keeffe?
She's a painter, duh.
She does these vagina pictures.
Or paintings, or just painted.
I don't know.
What are you even talking about?
Look, man, why am I even
explaining myself to you,
all right? It's none of your
damn business what I'm doing.
All you need to know
is I ain't cooking or shopping
or whatever the hell.
Let me explain something to you.
You and I need to cook
through to next Tuesday.
Tuesday? Four days straight?
Like it or not,
we have no choice.
Yeah? And why exactly is that?
Our methylamine. It's going bad.
What?
It's losing
its chemical potency.
Now, unless stealing another
barrel sounds good to you--
Hell, no.
All right, we have to act fast,
before it goes to waste.
You have a paper and pencil?
[GROANS]
Come on.
All right, all right.
Go.
JESSE:
Okay, six mantles.
Mantle? Mantle?
What do you mean, mantle?
You mean like Mickey?
SKYLER:
I really wish
you didn't have to do this.
Me too.
But I'll be back
before you know it,
and you can always call
if you need me.
What, and risk
talking to your mother?
Have to be some emergency.
Love you.
Fly safe, okay?
Okay.
WOMAN [ON PA]:
The white zone is for immediate
loading and unloading
of passengers only.
No parking.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH
ON PA]
MAN [ON PA]:
Attention, passengers:
Please maintain visual contact
with your personal belongings
at all times.
Any bags left unattended
will be confiscated
by airport personnel.
You brought a meth lab
to the airport?
What? You said we were
in a hurry. I saved us a trip.
Yeah. Did you get
everything? All six?
Yeah.
With reflux condensers?
Yes. Like I said, yes.
Just go. Drive. Go, go.
Okay.
Wow. Good morning
to you too, man.
♪ Good morning, world
It's a brand new day ♪
♪ I'm packing my bags
And I'm getting away ♪
♪ I'm moving my legs
And my city type bones ♪
♪ I gotta get away
From the busy man's phones ♪
♪ Down in Malibu where the
Living is so wild and free ♪
♪ If you wanna get happy then
People, come along with me ♪
♪ A bee bow bow
Buppa bow bow bow ♪
♪ Buppa bow bow bow ♪
♪ A bee bow bow
Buppa bow bow bow ♪
Stupid--
Three entire bags of Funyuns?
What?
Funyuns are awesome.
God.
Hey, more for me.
How about something
with some protein maybe?
Something green, huh?
Oh, man, I'm--
I'm getting no service.
[DIALING PHONE]
How are you even alive?
Hey, uh, yo, check your phone.
You get any bars?
Yeah, I've got a signal.
Yo, let me use yours,
would you?
Absolutely not.
I have to assume Skyler
checks my phone records.
You know that.
It's not business, all right?
It's personal.
Oh, personal.
What, female?
Maybe.
[LAUGHS]
Absolutely.
That's all I need.
Skyler hits redial
and some stripper answers.
Look, she's not a stripper,
okay? Dickwad.
Sorry. My wife checks.
Drinking water?
Yup.
Is that all we've got?
Ten gallons? What, you plan
on taking a bath in it?
Oh, God.
No, not there.
That is our workstation.
Oh, our "workstation."
That's right.
Why don't you try
to find a place
where it won't get lost, hm?
Considering
it's our only set,
and we are a million miles
from nowhere.
Why don't you try sticking them
up your ass sideways?
♪ Ready or not ♪
[GENERATOR RUNNING]
[THE BLACK SEEDS'
"ONE BY ONE" PLAYING]
♪ Summon everything
You've got ♪
♪ All your forces
Under the sun ♪
♪ Put the corn
Up into the sky ♪
♪ I'll take you
One by one by one ♪
♪ Come on and take me on ♪
♪ The sun's the only one
Who sleeps ♪
♪ I can hear everything
You say ♪
♪ There's a small piece
Of earth ♪
♪ Between you and me ♪
♪ We can play fight
Or we can play ♪
♪ Come on and take me on ♪
♪ 'Cause when the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ Well, I'll be lying
In the sun ♪
♪ When the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ We'll be lying in the sun ♪
♪ Yeah, when the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ We'll be lying in the sun ♪
Two-point-three-five pounds.
Two-point-three-five.
That's the last of it.
How many total?
Nineteen.
So, uh, dollar-wise?
How much?
Well, median weight
2.2 pounds,
that's 41.8,
call that 42 pounds at-- What
are we selling for these days?
Forty a pound.
Forty thousand dollars?
Hey, you said raise the prices.
All right,
that's 40 times 42,
minus distribution charges...
What?
Hm.
Six hundred seventy-two
thousand dollars.
All in?
No.
Each.
Each?
Six hundred and--?
Seventy-two thousand dollars
each.
Each. Yes! Hell, yeah!
Hey, come high, baby.
Come on. Yes. Come on.
[BOTH SHOUTING]
Yes! Yes!
[GENERATOR STOPS]
Well,
there goes the generator.
I think that's it
for the gas.
Perfect timing, yo.
How do you figure that?
What do you mean?
We're done cooking.
I am not done
until this barrel is empty.
Look at this.
I'd say we've still got 10,
12 gallons of methylamine.
Come on, where's your ambition?
Jesus. Seriously?
We are way ahead of schedule,
man, all right?
Plus the genny needs gas,
we're almost out of propane,
and my back is killing me
from that piece-of-crap cot.
Come on, can we at least
just take the night off?
Look, I don't have to take
you back till Tuesday, right?
So we come back tomorrow,
strap on the sizzle
and glass up the rest.
Come on.
There's gotta be a Denny's
out there someplace.
Grand Slam?
Hot shower?
A bed?
[JESSE LAUGHING]
Separate rooms.
Um, yeah, that's a given.
What the hell?
What the--?
The battery's dead.
Jesse,
back when I asked you
to put the keys
in a safe place,
where did you put them?
I left them right here
in the ignition.
Son of a bitch.
Whoa, whoa, no,
this is not my fault, all right?
The buzzer didn't buzz.
The what?
The buzz-- The buzzer that
buzzes when you put the keys in
to, like, let you know
that the battery's on.
I know that.
It didn't buzz.
Look, I didn't turn the key
or anything, all right?
I'm not stupid.
Did you hear the buzzer buzz?
I did not. It's faulty.
It's a faulty mechanism.
Is this just a genetic thing
with you? Is it congenital?
Did your mother drop you on your
head when you were a baby?
The buzzer did not buzz.
And you're the one that made me
move the keys
in the first place.
Yes, I see your point.
Your imbecility being what it
is, I should've known to say:
"Jesse, don't leave the keys
in the ignition
the entire two days."
I wanted to leave them
on the counter, bitch.
Oh, I'm sorry,
oh, the workstation.
Jesus.
Okay, just--
All right, so we need
to jump the battery somehow.
Okay.
How?
[COUGHING AND GAGGING]
You gonna be okay?
Oh, damn it.
What's it taste like?
Bad, huh?
This is good.
This is good. Right here.
Okay. There.
Here. Red to red,
black to black.
Positive, negative.
All right.
Start it up.
What the hell's wrong
with this thing?
You have to really pull.
Uh, I am.
No, really pull,
not like a girl.
You know what? Pull this.
I am pulling.
It just needs to warm
up a little. All right.
Oh, my God.
Oh, jeez.
Oh.
Well done, Jesse,
as always. Just--
Well done.
God.
[♪♪♪]
Come on, you bitches.
Hear me now.
Damn it.
[PHONE BEEPING]
Stupid.
Okay, now we have to use
your phone.
This is ruined.
Do you understand? Just ruined.
Yeah, you hooked it up wrong
and blew it up.
No, no, no, no, no.
That is not what happened.
How do you know?
What I know
is that I wasn't the one
who dumped out
the last of our water.
That's what I know.
There was a fire.
Excuse me for thinking
on my feet.
Oh. Is that what you were--?
You were thinking?
Ah. Now that we have
identified the problem--
You and thinking,
that's the problem.
Look,
somebody is going to
have to pick us up, all right?
Your wife is not gonna
notice one little call.
[SCOFFS]
Mr. White, come on.
God.
All right, look,
just make it--
Make it snappy.
Roaming drains the battery.
All right.
Yo, Skinny, hey.
Yeah, yeah. Listen, man,
I need you to come pick us up.
Now, all right?
We're stuck out here.
You got a pen
for directions?
Look, pencil's fine,
retard.
Just something to write with.
It doesn't matter.
All right, so you ready?
All right, so you're gonna
head west on the 40 for like,
what, 30 miles?
And you're gonna go past
the casino
with the big arrows
in the parking lot.
All right--
No, big arrows, giant arrows.
They light up and blink
and shit. You can't miss them.
Then you're gonna
wanna kind of take it slow,
'cause there's this dirt road.
It's right before the white sign
with a 3 on it, okay?
Now you're gonna be way,
way out in the boonies, okay?
Like crazy far,
so just keep heading down
that dirt road for like, what?
About another 15 miles.
Really? That far?
Yeah. Hurry up. The battery.
All right,
just go down that road
for like 15 more miles,
all right?
I mean, we're way the hell
out here. All right?
Oh, and, yo, hey, listen.
Um, bring water.
Leave now.
Here.
He's coming.
JESSE:
There was this guy
on the Discovery Channel
who broke his leg
mountain biking,
and he had to drink
urine for--
You know, just until
the forest ranger found him.
He said it tasted
like really hot,
really old soda.
Look, we should just call,
you know?
I'll be quick, just be like,
"Yo, where are you?"
All right.
[DIALING]
Come on.
Yo. Yo, where are you?
Oh, so you saw the white sign?
Yes, he's a-almost here.
Oh, man. We're getting
really freaked out.
All right, so you're, uh,
you're on the dirt road?
He's on the dirt road.
Good. Good.
You just crossed the river?
Yeah. Have you seen anything?
Wait, wait. What river?
Yeah, hey, yo, what river?
Dude, what the hell river you
talking about? There's no river.
Hey, yo, Pete.
Yo, Pete, can you--?
Phone's dead.
Now what?
Mr. White, what now?
Oh, come on. Seriously?
[WALT COUGHING]
[COUGHING]
What's this?
I'm trying to...
trickle-charge the battery.
Seriously?
Just by turning that thing?
The commutator.
It's the part
which generates the electricity.
Usually this little piston
engine turns it,
but considering that it's lying
here completely totaled...
Anyway.
Apply a little elbow grease.
It'll take longer,
a lot longer,
but theoretically,
it should work.
Oh. Theoretically.
It has to work.
You understand?
Can I try?
Yeah.
[COUGHING]
[♪♪♪]
JESSE:
How much longer?
I don't know.
Now?
Hey.
Mr. White.
Yeah?
Yo, man, you hanging in?
Yeah, I'm good.
It's gotta be ready by now,
right?
No, give it a little longer,
just to make sure we're--
[COUGHING]
Methylamine doesn't spoil,
does it?
No.
That's not why we're here.
Yo.
Lie much?
WALT:
Here, push.
[GRUNTING]
Okay, okay, okay.
Now.
Go on.
Please, please, please.
Yes. Yes.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE STOPS]
Come on.
Damn. No, please, God.
No. God.
No. Please. Please.
Argh!
[SCREAMING]
[SOBBING]
Why couldn't I have just gone
to Santa Fe?
Why? Why?
[♪♪♪]
Mr. White.
Mr. White!
What are you doing?
Mr. White?
JESSE:
Oh, God.
WALT:
I have this coming.
What?
I have it coming.
I deserve this.
Hey, snap out of it.
All right, first off,
everything you did,
you did for your family.
Right?
All I ever managed to do
was worry and disappoint them,
and lie.
Oh, God.
All the lies.
I can't even--
I can't even keep them straight
in my head anymore.
You know what?
Screw this.
I'm walking.
You can come or not.
Where's my other shoe?
Jesse. Jesse.
Your body
is running dangerously low
on electrolytes.
Sodium, potassium,
calcium.
And when they're gone,
your brain ceases to communicate
with your muscles.
Your lungs stop breathing,
your heart stops pumping.
You go marching out there
and within an hour,
you will be dead.
Okay, you need to cut out
all your loser crybaby crap
right now
and think of something
scientific.
Something--
Something scientific, right.
What? Come on, man.
You're smart, all right?
You made poison out of beans,
yo.
All right, look. We got--
We got an entire lab
right here, all right?
How about you take
some of these chemicals
and mix up some--
Some rocket fuel?
And we can just send up
a signal flare.
Or you make some kind of robot
to get us help,
or a homing device
or build a new battery or...
Or wait, no.
What if we just take some stuff
off of the RV
and build it into something
completely different?
You know, like a--
Like a dune buggy.
And that way,
we can just dune-buggy or--
What? Hey.
What is it?
What?
Do you--
Do you have any money?
Change, I mean. Coins.
Yeah, I got a bunch from the--
Okay.
Yes.
Gather them.
A-A-And washers and nuts
and bolts and screws
and whatever little pieces
of metal
we can think of
that is galvanized.
It has to be galvanized
or-- Or solid zinc.
Solid zinc, okay.
A-A-And-- And bring me--
Bring me brake pads.
The front wheels
should have discs.
Take them off
and bring them to me.
Okay. Brake pads, okay.
Brake pads.
What are we building?
You said it yourself.
A robot?
A battery.
Yes.
Move!
This doesn't look like
any battery I ever saw.
Well, trust me,
it is a battery.
Or rather,
one cell of a battery.
Here. Cut up
the last two sponges.
Remember the electrolytes?
Huh? Well, think about it.
A battery is a galvanic cell.
It's no more than an anode
and a cathode,
separated by an electrolyte,
right?
Right.
Yeah, well, anyway.
Here. On one side,
you have mercuric oxide
and graphite
from your brake pads.
This is the cathode.
This is the positive terminal.
This is where the--
The supply of current
flows out from, you see?
Then-- Here, I'll show you.
On the opposite side
is our anode.
This.
It's zinc.
It's what we find in our--
Find in our coins
and anything galvanized.
So the, uh, the sponge
is the electrolyte?
Yeah.
Well, no, the potassium
hydroxide is the electrolyte.
But, yes, that's what
I'm soaking the sponges in.
Good.
[CHUCKLES]
Good. And now,
what shall we use
to conduct this beautiful
current with, hm?
What one particular element
comes to mind, hm?
Hm?
Oh. Wire.
Oh.
Copper.
Oh, I mean--
Right.
The only question now is
will this supply enough current?
And how many cells
will we need?
We've only got material
enough for six.
Okay.
[COUGHING]
Put the lid on.
Wait. Positive.
All right.
Cathode.
Anode.
Damn. That is good.
That is very good.
Okay. Here we go.
Come on.
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[ENGINE RUNNING]
[LAUGHS THEN COUGHS]
MAN [ON PA]:
Attention, passengers:
Please maintain visual contact
with your personal belongings
at all times.
Any bags left unattended
will be confiscated by...
How's the, uh--?
Uh.
It's fine.
I know I can
trust you to, uh...
Yeah.
Hey, whatever happens,
your family
will get your share.
Thank you.
So, um...
I'll be hearing from you,
yeah?
Yeah.
DELCAVOLI:
How's everyone doing?
Is that baby ever gonna
come out, you think?
[LAUGHS]
I know. I know, enough already.
It's--
I'm teasing.
[LAUGHS]
Everything in its time.
Walt, I have your scan results.
Yeah.
And you're showing signs
of remission.
Oh, my God.
DELCAVOLI: I wanna clarify.
There are some misconceptions
about what remission
actually signifies.
It does not mean
that the patient is cured.
To classify someone
as in remission,
we only need to determine
that the tumor hasn't grown.
That it hasn't grown?
Jesus.
DELCAVOLI:
Technically speaking,
a tumor can remain the exact
same size it was before
and the patient
could still be in remission.
Now, in Walt's case,
with a stage III adenocarcinoma,
I'd like to see, I hope to see,
at least a 25- to 35-percent
reduction in tumor mass,
something to tell me
that the cancer
has responded to the therapy.
Everybody still with me?
And how has
my cancer responded?
Walt, your tumor has shrunk
by 80 percent.
Wow.
Oh, my God.
Wait, wait, wait. I'm sorry.
Wait, I'm really, um--
I'm confused.
Is--? Is--?
Isn't 80 percent a lot?
WALT JR.:
Mom, yeah.
Yes, 80 percent is a lot.
Okay, but, I'm-- Wait--
Sweetheart, you were right.
It's very good news.
DELCAVOLI: It's very good news.
Oh, my God.
My God,
are you kidding me?
Just when I try to get out,
they pull me back in.
[LAUGHING]
[BOTH SOBBING]
That's great.
[COUGHING]
Now, that cough is the other
thing we need to discuss.
According to your scan, Walt,
you have radiation pneumonitis.
It's okay.
This is fairly common.
See that scary-looking thing
there?
That's tissue inflammation.
It's a reaction
to your radiotherapy.
It's usually not serious,
but it can produce
a cough like that.
I'll prescribe some prednisone.
Tissue inflammation? I--
Are you sure about that?
I mean, I--
Because the other day,
I was coughing up some blood.
What?
DELCAVOLI:
You probably have
a tear in your esophagus
from the coughing,
and that can be very serious.
You could rupture
and bleed to death.
This is something
we're gonna have to deal with
before you leave here today.
Wait a minute.
Walt, when did this happen?
Why didn't you tell me?
I'm sorry, I just--
DELCAVOLI: No more secrets.
With something like this,
you have to call me immediately.
Now, with these results, we're
not completely out of the woods.
But now at least
we have some options,
the most important of which
is time.
We'll have more to discuss
in the next few weeks.
But for now, I'd say
that you folks have earned
some celebrating.
[SKYLER & HANK LAUGHING]
Yes.
WALT JR.: Yeah.
Oh, my God.
[♪♪♪]
[COUGHS]
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
♪ 'Cause when the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ Well, I'll be lying
In the sun ♪
♪ When the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ We'll be lying in the sun ♪
♪ Yeah, when the war is over
The fight is done ♪
♪ We'll be lying in the sun ♪