[♪♪♪]
[CHATTER OVER RADIO]
[COUGHS]
You're not thinking about
going to work today, are you?
Thought I would.
That inhaler really seems to be
doing the trick.
What?
Just take the rest of the week.
Please. You've earned it.
Don't push it.
Besides, I want you well
for the weekend.
Mom wants to party.
It's just a little get-together,
that's all.
Sunday afternoon, maybe?
You know, nothing too big.
Just family
and a few friends.
We've got a lot to celebrate.
Don't you think?
Sounds good.
Oh, thank you.
Now,
what are you supposed
to do today?
Nothing.
Excellent.
Brownie points
for taking a nap.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR PULLS AWAY]
[♪♪♪]
[RINGS]
Can you meet?
JESSE:
I thought maybe you
might have, you know,
kicked.
Signed--
Signed off.
I was even checking
the obits.
No such luck.
So, um,
where does it stand?
Coughing up blood,
giving speeches, you know, like:
"I deserve this.
I'm an asshole."
What's the upshot?
The upshot.
The upshot is that I have
radiation pneumonitis.
Damn.
Actually, it's not
as bad as it sounds.
It's a fairly
common occurrence,
easily treated.
In fact,
the news is all good.
What do you mean,
good?
You mean, like,
"good" good?
What, you mean, like,
remission good?
Remission.
Not to imply I'm cured.
I still have cancer.
But there's been a significant
reduction in the tumors.
How significant?
Eighty percent.
Dude. No way.
Now, I'm not out of the woods
yet, not by any stretch, but...
"options" is the word
they keep bandying about.
That's awesome.
Serious?
That's--
That's great, man.
I mean, my aunt, she never--
I mean, you know, at your stage,
I didn't think
that could happen.
Yeah.
Mr. White,
you kicked its ass, yo!
No. You must be so psyched.
Of course. I am.
Okay, now we...
I mean, what do we...?
Oh, hey, I almost forgot.
So how do you
want to,
you know, proceed
in light of this
kick-ass news?
We'll take our time
and stay cautious.
Sell off what we have.
And then, uh...
Well, then I guess...
I'm done.
[WANG CHUNG'S "DANCE HALL DAYS"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CHATTER]
Batter up.
SKYLER: Um, everyone?
Hey, you guys.
I would like to make a toast
with my non-alcoholic beverage.
HANK:
Somebody kill the music.
I know one party
can't begin to repay
all your support and your--
Your many, many kindnesses.
But then again,
Hank does make
one mean margarita.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Um...
We really do want
to thank you.
These last few months
have been, uh...
wow, a challenging time,
to put it mildly.
But, um,
I have to say Walt's
come through it like a champ.
MAN 1: All right.
SKYLER: I'm so proud of you.
MAN 2:
We all are.
Oh.
Okay, I'm gonna stop
with the sappy stuff. I am.
But it's true. It really is.
And, um, for the first time
in a long time,
we are so excited
about the future.
Okay, anyway, um, I--
Ooh, I want to also
express my gratitude
to two very special people
who couldn't be here today.
But, um, they send their regrets
and their warm wishes.
Gretchen and Elliott Schwartz,
for those of you
who don't know them, are...
um, well, they're heroes.
They are incredibly
generous friends
who made the amazing offer
to pay for Walt's treatment.
And, um,
and they did.
So...
to Gretchen and Elliott.
GUESTS: To Gretchen and Elliot.
WOMAN 1: Cheers.
Hey, how about the man
of the hour? Come on.
Speech.
Yes.
CARMEN: Speech.
WALT JR.: Yeah, Dad.
WOMAN 2:
Come on, Walt. Speech.
Um...
Ahem. Well, it's...
It's kind of funny.
When I got my diagnosis,
cancer,
I said to myself,
you know:
"Why me?"
And then...
the other day,
when I got the good news...
I said the same thing.
Ha.
Anyway.
Uh... Thank you for coming.
And enjoy.
HANK: All right, cheers.
WOMAN 3: Yeah.
Cheers.
Wow.
Inspirational.
HANK:
Tell you what.
I gotta give those bastards
points for originality.
I'll tell you that much.
A little mercury switch,
9-volt battery,
five or six ounces of C-4,
that's how those
cartel boys party.
Yeah, but, um,
why a turtle?
Oh, that's the best part.
It was a, uh...
It was a... What the hell's
the word I'm looking for?
Not a metaphor, uh,
not an analogy, it's a...
Walt, what's the word
I'm looking for?
Anyway, uh, Tortuga.
Okay? That was the name
of our snitch.
Bean-speak
for tortoise. Okay?
Tortoise, turtle,
what have you.
I never-- Never knew
the difference myself.
Hey, uh, top me off there,
will you, buddy?
Anyway.
Poetic.
I guess, yeah.
Poetic. It was poetic.
That's the word.
I guess that's the word.
Go ahead.
Better not, uh,
let your mom see.
[WALT JR. CLEARS THROAT
THEN COUGHS]
[LAUGHING]
Oh, yeah, I think--
I think I see a hair.
Maybe two.
Th-- There's no worm
in this, right?
No,
that would be mescal.
Talk about your hangovers,
okay? Ooh.
I was down in
Glynco, Georgia.
I was back east,
doing some training.
Had this, uh, firearm instructor
who was, uh...
He was a good old boy, you know?
Hey. There you go. Thanks.
I mean,
this guy could put them away
like he had two livers,
okay?
Like a fish, okay?
Like a drunk fish.
We were drinking
mescal stupid.
But-- Hey, hey.
Walt,
what you doing there?
What does it look like
I'm doing?
The kid's 16.
What are you going for,
Father of the Year?
What are you
looking at him for?
Hm?
We're celebrating. Come on.
That's all right.
[COUGHING]
No.
Jesus.
Listen, I'd, uh, take a pass
on that one if I were you, okay?
Think we've been bogarting
this puppy long enough.
Heh, heh, heh.
Hey.
Bring the bottle back.
Sorry, buddy.
No can do.
It's my son.
My bottle. My house.
Heh, heh. It's all right.
What are you waiting for?
Bring it back.
Why don't we just call it a day?
All right, pal?
We good?
The bottle.
Now.
What's going on?
Jesus.
Here, sweetie.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God.
There you go.
[WALT JR. VOMITING]
SKYLER:
Okay. That's it.
Just get it out. That's okay.
JESSE:
This is your brain.
This is your brain on drugs.
Wow.
Uh...
You weren't supposed to
wake up.
Ever or...?
Heh, heh.
No, I was just thinking
that I'd bring it,
you know, in.
You want me to go
back to bed?
No, I guess
that'd be kind of--
[TIMER DINGS]
Uh, no.
Need some help?
No, I got it.
Ow. Ow. Ow.
Um, just, uh, have a seat.
Is there any coffee?
Uh, yeah, shit.
Um, one second.
Well, at least
let me do that.
No, I don't want you to have
to do anything, you know?
Mm.
All right. Here.
You take the good one.
It's, um, huevos rancheros.
I can tell.
Yeah?
Um...
Fork.
Oh, yeah.
Aha. There you go.
So, what are you
up to today? Working?
Whatever that means.
No.
I'm all yours.
Really?
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
[RINGING]
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, this is Skyler. Please
leave me a message. Thanks.
[VOICEMAIL BEEPS]
Hi.
I just wanted to say that...
No.
We'll talk tonight, but I...
I wanted to say that
I-I'm not exactly sure
who that was yesterday,
but it wasn't me, and...
I'm sorry.
Love you.
Oh, boy.
WALTER [ON RECORDING]:
I just wanted to say that...
No.
We'll talk tonight,
but I-- I wanted to say that...
TED:
Hey there.
Wow,
who brought the churros?
Oh, that would be me.
If I leave them at home,
I'll just wind up
eating them all myself, so...
[CHUCKLES]
They're actually--
They're leftovers.
We had a little get-together
for Walt.
It wasn't his birthday,
was it?
Uh, actually,
Walt's got...
He's been battling cancer.
Oh, Skyler--
And, um, last week
we got good news.
I'm so sorry.
But w-we're really optimistic.
Great.
Great. Good news is great.
Yeah.
Yeah, it is. It really is.
Well, um,
feel free to bring these
any time. Heh, heh, heh.
Yeah. Heh, heh.
[THE MARSHALL TUCKER BAND'S
"HEARD IT IN A LOVE SONG"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Got some real beauts.
Mm.
You cannot beat the thermal
efficiency of the C3.
Yeah?
Then again,
what about tankless?
Sure. We got them.
I mean, the good ones will
really run up your price though.
Set you back about,
uh, 1200.
Uh. It's not an issue.
BOB:
You want installation, right?
No.
I'm gonna do it myself.
That's what I like to hear.
JANE:
And who's this?
This guy can surf
without a board?
Um, that's Hover Man.
He can surf, skate, glide,
whatever,
because he's always got
a 6-inch cushion of air
under his feet.
That's cool.
Great lines.
And this guy?
What's his superpower?
That's, uh, Kanga-man.
Kanga-man?
Half-man, half-kangaroo?
And who's this in his pouch?
JESSE:
His, uh, sidekick, Joey.
He rides around
in his pouch and, you know,
fights crime.
So that makes
Kanga-man a she.
You know that, right?
Only female kangaroos
have pouches.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
But, you know,
it's definitely a dude.
He's a product
of experimentation.
He's kind of hot, I guess.
Nice haunches.
And this is?
It's, uh, Backwardo.
Wait, no. I actually--
I changed it to Rewindo.
Anyways, he goes backwards.
He can make everything
go in reverse.
Time and stuff?
Like time traveling?
No, he just, um...
he just walks backwards.
He walks backwards?
Is that a superpower?
What good is that?
No, I mean, he does it,
like, really fast.
You know? Okay, look,
say someone's coming
at him with a knife, right?
I mean, it's helpful.
Then he can just zip backwards
away from them.
Okay.
Yo, I was a kid
when I drew all these.
It was like four years ago.
They all look like you.
What?
It's you in all of these.
Nah. No.
I wonder what a shrink would say
if he saw them.
Oh, shut up.
Like you never wanted
a superpower.
[KNOCKING]
Is that your door or mine?
I don't know.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
It sounds like mine.
I gotta go.
Where?
Hey, where?
Hey, hold up.
Where are you...?
Jane.
Hey, Dad.
Ah, there you are.
Hi, honey.
I saw your car, so I was
pretty sure you were home.
Yeah, sorry. I was working.
I had my headphones on.
Finally realized that
I wasn't the drum track?
Exactly.
Well, I was in the neighborhood.
Was wondering if you wanted
to grab some lunch.
Sure. Yeah.
Hey,
this, uh, your dad?
Yes.
Hello.
Hi.
This is the new tenant.
Donald.
Jesse.
I'm sorry.
Did you need something?
Uh...
No.
Dad, why don't you come in?
It was nice seeing you.
It was nice to meet you.
You too.
WALT JR.:
Hey, Dad.
Oh. Hey, son. Heh.
Are you home early?
No.
Oh, man.
It was a good day?
Now it is. Finally, hot water.
No more toxic waste.
Yes. Yes, indeed.
Top of the line,
on demand, unlimited supply.
Sweet.
Yeah.
Hey, want to take her
for a spin?
Oh, yeah.
Heh, heh. All right.
Listen, why don't you
go to the kitchen sink?
Let me know when you're ready,
and I'll give you a holler.
Okay.
Pilot in.
Ignition. Bingo.
Okay.
WALT JR.: Ready.
All right. Let her rip.
Oh.
Ah.
Hundred and seventeen
thousand BTUs.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, yeah.
Built-in corrosion-resistant
draft reducer,
safety thermocouple
with the pilot burner.
Soun-- Sounds really good,
Dad.
And the energy savings.
I mean...
Ow.
Oh, oh.
Oh, careful,
careful, careful.
There's probably
some adjustments
I need to make there.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm-- I-I'm fine.
Okay.
Son,
about yesterday--
I-I'm sorry about the pool.
No, no, no, that was not
your fault. Not at all.
See, your...
Your old man
embarrassed himself,
and I'm not very proud
of my behavior.
I have to say
I feel very foolish.
Um, you and Uncle Hank,
y-you seemed pissed off.
No. No. We're fine.
Everything's fine.
I called him this morning
and made my apologies.
But, son, I owe you
an apology most of all.
I should have used
better judgment all around.
Having you drink in the first
place, i-it was not right,
and for that I-I'm very sorry.
But I kept up, right?
You and Uncle Hank.
I drank three.
I have some tools
to put away.
[AIR PURIFIER WHIRRING]
[KNOCKING]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Hey.
Uh, yo.
You want to
catch a movie later?
Yo.
What?
What was that
all about?
What?
Before.
With your dad.
It wasn't about
anything.
Oh, okay, so I totally
just misread your total dis?
If anything,
I was doing you a favor.
A favor?
Yeah, I told you.
He's a hard-ass.
He seemed cool to me.
Yeah, well.
So, what's the deal?
There's no deal.
I was helping you out,
okay? Protecting you.
How's that?
I mean...
I'm letting you smoke
in here and everything.
[SCOFFS]
I bought a filter.
And I figured the less he knows,
the better.
You acted like
you didn't even know me.
So?
You think I'm gonna be all like:
"Hey, Dad, meet the stoner guy
who lives next door.
And by the way,
I'm sleeping with him"?
That's all you think
you're doing?
Why do you even care
about my dad?
I don't.
Good. Then I don't know
why we're talking about it.
Us. All right?
I'm talking about us.
Us.
Yeah.
You and me.
Who's you and me?
I'm out of here.
[CHOPS & LIL WEAVAH'S
"MY RIMS" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
[BUZZING]
[WALT COUGHS]
[GRUNTING]
Oh, boy.
[SAW BUZZING]
Dad?
Dad? Hello?
What? Oh, hey.
What are you doing?
We've got rot.
Rot?
Yeah. Here.
I'll show you. Here.
Take a look at that.
See that? Yeah.
Ever seen anything like it?
It's wood.
It's wood
that contains fruiting bodies.
Fruity what?
Fungus.
And it is on a rampage.
I-I don't really see anything.
Yeah, well, it's there.
You just have
to know where to look. Here.
Then you cut it all out.
You just cut it out
and start fresh.
Well, better get to it.
I-Is the whole house
gonna collapse or something?
Not if I can help it.
[SAW WHIRRING]
[WHIRRING]
Hey. You bucking
for a promotion?
Go home already.
I will. Um. I will.
Hey, um,
can I just ask, um...
the Keller account?
The Keller account?
It's listed as a current asset
on this balance sheet, but, uh,
uh, the invoice
was never presented
to accounts receivable, so...
Oh, God.
One of these days I'm gonna just
sort through all the Dad stuff.
He had so many, you know,
"Don't worry about it,
pay me Friday" relationships
with these little companies.
We'll figure it out tomorrow.
Or not. Heh, heh.
Right. Ahem.
Seriously, you're not gonna
make me lock you in, are you?
Sky?
Skyler?
Jesus.
[CRYING]
No, I-I'm fine.
It's hormones. Honestly.
It happens all the time.
I'll see you tomorrow.
What's wrong?
I guess it just...
doesn't feel any different.
The, uh, good news?
I mean,
nothing's really changed.
It's just postponed.
There was supposed to be a light
at the end of the tunnel.
But, um...
lately, it just feels like...
More tunnel.
I'm sorry.
I just feel
so damn ungrateful.
I don't know.
For me, it was the flu.
What?
My dad rallied at the end.
I mean, it wasn't the full-on
good news Walt got,
different circumstances,
but we were happy,
we were over the moon.
And, uh, right then,
I got sick.
Flu. Boom.
Knocked me on my ass for days.
Couldn't get out of bed,
I couldn't move.
Great timing, huh?
Yeah.
And I-- I wasn't even putting
two and two together.
I was just thinking:
"Why now?"
Being that rock.
You know,
being that rock
takes everything you got.
Yeah.
[TOOLS CLATTERING]
[WALT GRUNTING]
[SIGHS]
[WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TV]
WOMAN [ON TV]:
--causing the housing prices
to spread.
Foreclosures are being fueled
by a spike in...
[METAL CLATTERS]
The economy is rapidly
deteriorating
and unemployment is climbing.
With Americans losing money
over rising inflation
and tight spending,
the housing market
is unlikely to rebound,
spelling more pain
for the economy.
WALT:
Oh. Yeah.
Mm.
Are you going
to work today?
Skyler, there's rot.
I'm going back.
[DRILL BUZZING]
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
TED:
All right. We'll take care of
that tomorrow. Okay, good night.
WOMAN: Good night, Ted.
Good night.
Oh, damn.
Mm.
Clumsy.
I got it.
No, no, Ted.
You don't have to do that.
[BUZZING]
MAN 1 [ON RECORDING OVER PA]:
Get organized. Storage
containers to meet every need,
big or small, on Aisle 3.
Stashing your stuff
has never been so easy.
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]:
Get a thicker, fuller lawn
in less than six weeks.
Why can't the grass
always be greener on your side?
Go to Aisle 10 to go green.
MAN 2:
Get a manager
on Checkout 4, please.
Manager to Checkout 4.
MAN 3 [ON RECORDING]:
Pest problems? No problem.
Your extermination destination
is Aisle 6.
You're buying
the wrong matches.
What?
Those matches.
They're
the wrong kind.
Red phosphorous is found
in the striker strips,
not the matches themselves.
You need to get the big
200-count box
of individual matchbooks.
More striker strips.
You understand?
Those only have the one.
And don't buy everything
in one place.
Do it piecemeal.
Different items, different
stores. Attracts less attention.
Huh?
Are you following me here?
MAN 4 [ON RECORDING]:
You've been putting off
refinishing that deck
long enough.
We have everything you need
to do the job right.
Ha.
Thanks.
Sure.
Next.
Hi. Here you go.
[SCANNER BEEPING]
[TV ON THE RADIO'S
"DLZ" PLAYS]
♪ Congratulations ♪
MAN 1: You didn't buy my stuff?
MAN 2: No, I didn't.
MAN 1:
We don't have time for this.
♪ Reconstruct the air
And all that brings ♪
♪ And oxidation is
The compromise you own ♪
Hey, there he is.
Th-That's the guy.
♪ Beginning to feel
Like the dog wants her bones ♪
♪ Say ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la,
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la ♪
Stay out of my territory.
♪ La, la, la, la, la,
La, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ This is beginning to feel ♪
♪ Like the long-winded blues
Of the never ♪
♪ Never you mind
Death professor ♪
♪ Your shocks are fine
My struts are better ♪
♪ Your fiction flies so high ♪
♪ Y'all could use a doctor
Who's sick? Who's next? ♪
♪ Never you mind
Death professor ♪
♪ Electrified ♪
♪ My love is better ♪
♪ It's crystallized, so am I ♪
♪ All could be the diamond
Fused with who's next ♪
♪ This is beginning to feel ♪
♪ Like the dawn of the luz
Of forever ♪
[♪♪♪]