[CREAKING]
[SIRENS APPROACHING]
[♪♪♪]
[CLICKS]
[BUZZING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO]
[HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING]
[♪♪♪]
[BED CREAKING]
[JESSE GRUNTING]
JESSE:
Come on.
Come--
Come on. Come on, baby.
Please, please.
Come on, come on. Come on!
[SOBBING]
Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
[BEEPS]
Yeah.
Slow down. Slow-- Slow down.
Now, just--
Just take a deep breath.
Do it.
All right.
Now, what happened?
All right. All right.
Now, listen-- Listen to me.
Are you listening?
Everything is gonna be okay.
I promise.
No, no-- Listen. Calm down.
Just--
Sit tight.
I know who to call.
Saul Goodman sent me.
Come on. Inside.
Latch the door.
Where is she?
Any other drugs in the house?
Think hard.
Your freedom depends on it.
What about guns?
You got any guns in the house?
Here's your story.
You woke up. You found her.
That's all you know.
Say it.
Say it, please.
"I woke up. I found her.
That's all I know."
[SOBBING]
Say it. "I woke up. I found her.
That's all I know."
I woke up. I found her.
That's all I know.
Again.
I woke up. I found her.
That's all I know.
Again. Again.
I woke up. I found her.
That's all I know.
Once you call,
the people who show up
will be with the Office
of Medical Investigations.
That's primarily
who you'll talk to.
Police officers may arrive,
they may not.
Depends on how busy
a morning they're having.
Typically, ODs are not
a high-priority call.
There's nothing here
to incriminate you
so I'd be amazed if you
got placed under arrest.
However, if you do,
you say nothing.
You tell them you
just want your lawyer.
Then you call Saul Goodman.
And do I need
to state the obvious?
I was not here.
You put on a long-sleeved shirt
and cover those track
marks on your arm.
Count down from 20,
and then you dial.
Hang tough.
You're in the home stretch.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR SHUTS]
WALT:
Do you want 2-percent or skim?
Uh-- Two. Two.
Two. All right.
Thank you.
Mm-hm.
Junior.
Flynn.
What?
WALT JR.:
I'll be there in a minute.
You all right?
Flynn, get your butt in here.
WALT JR.:
Oh, my God. Mom, Dad, come here.
You gotta see this.
Seriously.
What?
Look right there. Look at that.
Are those donations?
WALT JR.:
Yes.
SKYLER:
Actual donations for your dad?
WALT JR.:
Total strangers gave us $490.
Twenty-six people.
Virginia, Minnesota, Montana.
Look at this one. Vancouver.
All the way up in Canada.
And-- And-- And it's all real,
actual money.
It's actually right-right
there in the PayPal account.
And-and look--
Look what they're saying:
"Hang in there, Walt."
"Good luck."
"Hang in there."
Is-Isn't this awesome?
That's--
Wow, that is something.
Walt, don't you think
a little thank-you is in order?
Yes, absolutely. Thank you, son.
Thank you. This is a big--
Big help. Heh-heh.
[BELL DINGS ON COMPUTER]
WALT JR.:
Oh, look, 20 more bucks
from Thunder Bay, Ontario.
Damn. Five--
Five hundred and ten dollars.
[PHONE RINGING]
JANE [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, if you're trying
to sell me something,
I've got four little
words for you:
"Do-not-call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
How did I know you wouldn't
be answering your phone?
I'm on my way.
I'm gonna be there momentarily.
I expect you on the porch,
bag packed, ready to go.
No excuses.
Sir, you may not wanna
be here for this.
Um, I just, uh, woke up
and, uh, I found her.
That's all I know.
What's her date of birth?
Um...
[SNIFFLES]
INVESTIGATOR:
Sir, your daughter's
date of birth?
DONALD:
April...
April 4th, 1982.
Okay.
And mother's maiden name
and place of birth.
My mother?
Your daughter's mother.
Uh, Bishop.
And place of birth?
Phoenix.
INVESTIGATOR:
Phoenix, Arizona?
This is our address.
Do you have someone
who can drive you?
I can drive.
Well, then if you'd like
to meet us there,
we can complete the intake
and take our samples,
and then you can make
your arrangements.
Okay?
Now, do you need a card?
Will you both be coming?
[DOOR OPENS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON RADIO]
[BELL DINGS ON COMPUTER]
I don't believe it.
Walt, you have to see this.
Forty from Te--
Terre Haute.
Walt!
WALT:
It's me.
Are you there? Hello.
I'm, um, just checking in.
Our friend says he thinks
everything went well.
Uh-- That's-- That's good.
So listen.
Just call me, all right?
SKYLER:
Hey, Walt, you've
gotta come in here.
We just broke
a thousand dollars.
[FLUSHING]
Wow. All right. I'm--
I'm coming.
HANK:
All right. Some of you already
know my brother-in-law.
He's a good man.
The doctors say this operation
has a real chance
of helping him.
Of course, they're also
saying they wanna be paid
in private islands
so dig deep.
Biggest donation
gets a six-pack
of my very own Schraderbrau.
Home-brewed to silky perfection.
Smallest donation
gets two six-packs.
All right. All right.
Other than Gomie here
pees sitting down,
here's what we know.
Christian Ortega, a.k.a. Combo.
Shot dead by an unknown
assailant last month.
"Combo?" I hear you say.
"Why, I'm unfamiliar
with that name.
Was he a Nobel laureate
perchance?"
No. He was a dipshit
wannabe banger.
Now, no arrests,
save for stealing a baby Jesus
from a Knights of Columbus
manger back when he was 17.
This dude was so low-rep
he never showed up on our radar.
So why am I talking about him?
Anyone? Anyone?
Bueller?
He was dealing Blue Sky.
That's right.
Now, how is it that the purest,
most professional grade
of meth we've ever come across
is being slung
by the likes of that?
But wait. It gets better.
Since, oh-uh, baby-Jesus thief
there slowed a bullet
with his neck,
the blue stuff's
vanished from town, okay?
Not a speck to be found
in Albuquerque.
Now, why is that?
Well, because maybe
your Heisenberg's in prison.
So says A.P.D.
They think they got their man.
I know you don't buy it,
but maybe it's true.
James Edward Kilkelly, yeah.
A.P.D. thinks this
is our mastermind.
You believe that,
I got a bridge to sell you.
Hey, he copped to it, didn't he?
What, for an extra pudding cup
every night at Los Lunas, huh?
Maybe, uh, if you give him
a pack of cigarettes,
he'll tell you what
he did with Jimmy Hoffa.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
I've been thinking.
Top-shelf product like this?
It doesn't fall off
the face of the earth, okay?
The way I see it, raw talent's
bound to pop up somewhere.
It's like Whack-A-Mole.
So I've been making phone calls.
Local police departments,
small-town sheriffs.
Haven't had much luck
inside the Land of Enchantment.
But outside, I've got reports
of the blue stuff
making a scene here in Texas,
Arizona, Colorado, and Nevada.
In fact, everywhere but here.
Almost as if somebody wised up,
stopped shitting where they eat.
Now, I say Heisenberg's
still out there.
I say he's gone regional.
Only he's still
right here in town.
Come on, 2800.
Come on, big 28.
You can do it.
Only 30 more dollars.
Thirty more.
[BELL DINGS ON COMPUTER]
[GASPS]
Fo-- Forty dollars!
Twenty-eight ten.
Yes!
Yes! Ha-ha-ha.
SKYLER:
Who's gonna be next?
WALT:
Your guy found him?
Where is he?
Okay, listen.
No, no, I don't care.
You have your guy pick--
Saul. Just shut-- Saul.
Saul, shut up
and give me the address.
MAN:
I don't recommend it.
A.P.D.'s been known
to sit on this place,
keep an eye
on the comings and goings.
Are they here now?
Well, I don't see any sign,
but that's the point.
Police could be the least of it.
You could just
get mugged or shot.
How about you go on home,
Walter?
Let me handle this.
Yo.
[MAN COUGHING]
[MOANING]
Jesse.
Jesse. Jesse.
Look at me, son.
Wake up. Wake up.
Hey.
I ain't got nothing
for you, man. It's all gone.
Jesse, damn it,
wake up. Just--
Jesse, Jesse.
Jesse, it's me.
Okay, it's me.
It's Walt. It's Walt.
Jesse.
Yeah.
Come on, let's get out of here.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm good.
Come on. Help me out now.
I'm good. I'm good.
Right here, man. Right here.
Listen, Jesse,
you are not good right here.
You are not good at all.
You hear?
Now, you just put your arms
around me. Come on.
You're gonna stand up,
and we're gonna-- We're gonna
walk out of here, okay?
We're gonna take you
someplace nice and safe.
That's it. Now, let's go.
Come on. Here we go.
[SOBBING]
WALT:
Shh, shh, shh.
I killed her.
What?
I killed her. It was me.
I killed her, man. I killed her.
No.
Jesse, look at me. Look at me.
You didn't kill anybody.
I loved her.
I loved her more than anything.
No, no. No.
[♪♪♪]
I haven't given much thought
to the programs, to be honest.
I guess they should be, uh...
I don't know. Just--
Just use your best judgment.
There's no yellow dress here.
It's all--
It's all black and gray.
When's the last time you saw her
ever wearing a yellow dress?
What about blue?
Blue's better than black, right?
No, no. Not dark blue.
More like--
Well, um--
Not super-bright, either.
I mean, blue is blue.
No. No cleavage.
Long sleeves.
Yeah. It's nice.
It's nice.
[YAWNS]
Oh, big, big yawn, Holly.
I know what you feel like.
I'm tired too.
Okay, sweetie.
WALT JR.: Yes.
[BELL DINGS ON COMPUTER]
Yes.
Here we go.
Here we go. Yes.
[BELL DINGS ON COMPUTER]
Would you mind turning
that thing down or off?
Junior. Hey.
The dinging.
Just turn down the volume.
Dad, it-- It's money.
Just please do it, okay.
The noise
is disturbing the baby.
SKYLER:
Marie, slow down. I can't--
Oh, my God. You are kidding me.
Sure. Of course.
Any day after school.
Okay, um. Wait. I'm gonna--
Let me tell him
and I'll call you right back.
Okay.
[BEEPS OFF]
Guess what.
What?
You are gonna
be in the newspaper.
N-No way.
One of Aunt Marie's patients
works at the Journal,
when she told him about
the website and the donations,
he went to his editor,
and they're gonna
do a story about you.
For real?
Yep.
They're coming to interview you
with a photo and everything.
WALT JR.:
Awesome.
It'll mean more hits.
And more contributions.
Wow.
HANK:
East of Scottsdale?
Let me guess. Not talking.
[SIGHS]
Nope. Not a one.
Somebody somewhere
is running one tight ship.
All right, chief. Yeah.
Thanks a lot.
Yeah. You too.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
ASAC:
Agent Schrader,
can you spare a moment?
Yes, sir. Absolutely.
Gentlemen, this is Supervising
Agent Hank Schrader.
Agent Schrader,
I'd like you to meet
Andrew Coffman
of the Adobe Hotel.
Hey, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Paul Canterna
of Canterna Real Estate.
Hey, it's a pleasure.
Good to meet you.
And Gustavo Fring
of Los Pollos Hermanos.
Please, just Gus.
Hi, Gus.
Gotta tell you, you guys
make some killer chicken.
Ha-ha, thank you very much.
These gentlemen are underwriting
this year's Fun Run,
and I thought
I would give them a tour.
Absolutely. Get to see
what you're supporting.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Can you tell us a little
about your work here?
Oh, yes, the Albuquerque office
covers everything from
drug-related money laundering
to interdiction of illicit
substances crossing the border.
Now, the group that I supervise
focuses on methamphetamine,
which is a growing problem
in the country, unfortunately.
Terrible.
HANK: Yeah. It is indeed.
Now, we've had some
successes locally,
but overall the supply
seems to be growing.
I gotta tell you,
community outreach,
like this Fun Run,
one of the most powerful
weapons we have.
Anything we can do.
Thank you.
Thank you, Hank.
Gentlemen.
Thanks.
Sure. Thank you.
Is this one of your agents?
Oh, uh, yeah, no, no, that's--
That's my brother-in-law.
He's got a health issue.
We're-- We're trying to--
Oh, I'm-- I'm very sorry.
What--?
What sort of health issue?
Lung cancer.
Oh, that's a rough one.
Oh, hey, hey, you don't--
You don't have to do that.
Please. Please. I'm--
I'm happy to do it.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
[♪♪♪]
Uh, just so you know,
I won't be back for a while.
I'm gonna have
my surgery on Friday.
I'm hopeful it'll go well.
But if not,
Saul will take care of things.
He's got your money.
He's keeping it for you.
Look, Jesse, lingering on things
doesn't help, believe me.
Just try and focus
on getting better, okay?
I deserve this.
What?
What you said in the desert.
I get it, what you meant.
I deserve whatever happens.
Oh, shit.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Oh, oh. There he is.
[WHISPERING]
Walt, they're doing
a feature on Walter Jr.
We called you about 50 times.
Marie, I thought we were just
talking about a newspaper story.
Yeah, yeah, I know, I know,
but I thought, you know,
if it's good enough
for the Journal,
then why not TV?
So I went for it.
This is him?
Yes.
This is Dad. Great.
Let's get everyone over
here on the couch.
I'm thinking Walt Jr.
in the middle,
Mom and Dad on either side.
Mom and Dad?
How much money
have you raised so far?
Six thousand, three hundred
and sixty dollars,
but there's more
coming in all the time.
Wow, that's amazing.
SKYLER:
We don't even know what to say.
It's just--
It's been incredible.
REPORTER:
Judging from the things you
and other folks have
written about him,
your dad must be quite a guy.
Yeah. He is. He's the best.
You don't wanna lose him,
do you, Walter?
WALT JR.:
N-n-none of us do.
We love him.
REPORTER:
He's a good man, isn't he?
WALT JR.:
Absolutely. Ask anyone.
Anybody. He's a great father,
a great teacher.
He knows, like, everything there
is to know about chemistry.
He's patient with you,
and he's always there for you.
He's-- He's just decent.
And he always
does the right thing.
And that's how
he teaches me to be.
REPORTER:
Would you say he's your hero?
WALT JR.:
Oh, yeah. Yes, ma'am. Totally.
M-My dad is my hero.
D-D-Does that put him to sleep?
This one just relaxes
him a little.
We're almost ready.
We'll be taking you in
in just a minute.
Okay. Thank you.
Well...
Here we are.
Yeah.
R-R-Relax--
Relaxed yet?
As a matter of fact...
Wow.
I don't know what this stuff is,
but it's pretty great.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Yeah, it looks like it.
[CHUCKLES]
We'll be here when you wake up.
Well, I'll be looking for you.
Oh, they'll probably want
me to take your glasses.
Mm. Yeah, you better.
Yeah, okay.
Okay. I got them.
[CHUCKLES]
Where's your phone?
Hm?
Your cell phone.
Did you bring it?
Which one?
WALT JR.:
I'm-- I'm pret--
I'm pretty sure he didn't--
He didn't bring it, Mom.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
♪ Oh, there's a receipt
Where my money goes ♪
♪ Who need some new food
And 10 pounds of clothes ♪
♪ Wrapped in a dare
President's wife ♪
♪ Scissors and rock
Paper and knife ♪
♪ It's big and it's slow
Roses in rain ♪
♪ Black in its good light
Pleasure and pain ♪
♪ It's life ♪
♪ Life ♪
DELCAVOLI:
Well, first things first.
How old is that baby now?
When do I get to meet her?
You know I was actually thinking
of bringing her today, but...
She's, um, seven weeks tomorrow.
Se-- Seven, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, oh, hey, I have a--
A picture here somewhere.
Ah. Heh.
Oh. She's beautiful.
Thanks.
Always a relief to say that
and actually mean it.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
How's your pain level, Walt?
Uh, it's-- It--
Very low, basically.
BRAVENEC:
Shortness of breath?
A bit, but much better.
BRAVENEC: Good.
Well, your margins look good.
Obviously, I can't
foresee the future,
but even conservatively
speaking,
I can say that you bought
yourself some real time here.
There's no reason
not to be optimistic.
That's great. Heh.
That is great.
Thank you, doctor.
So, um, when could he get back
to his normal routine?
He can ease into it now.
Okay.
And, uh, can he go
back to work or..?
I'd give it a few more weeks.
Make sure you avoid
any heavy lifting
and continue to get
plenty of rest.
Um, but he can be on his own?
I mean, just more,
you know, independent.
Yes. Use your best judgment.
Okay.
Well...
Now, that's good news
for you, huh, honey?
Heh. One less baby in the house.
Don, hey.
Hey, Stew.
Hey, welcome back.
Thanks. It's good to be back.
Jesus. We-- We were all
so sorry to hear.
Yes. Thanks.
Terrible thing. Just...
But you know, we've all been
thinking about you and, uh,
you been doing okay?
I'm doing okay.
After a certain point,
time off doesn't help
so I figured I'd rather be here.
Focus on work.
Sure. Absolutely.
Yeah.
Well, see you inside.
MAN:
Continue to descend
through 1500.
DONALD:
Headed downwind for a left base
on Runway 17.
Number 26-Tango,
descend to maintain 13,000.
Truth or Consequences altimeter,
two-niner-niner-eight.
Pima-311, contact
Albuquerque Center 134.6.
Juliet-5-Bravo,
ident, say altitude.
Juliet-5-Bravo, roger.
Clear direct to Winslow.
I think I may just keep this.
Sky?
What do you think? Hm?
Doesn't look so bad, right?
What are you doing?
I'm going to Hank and Marie's
for the weekend.
Since when?
I'm taking the baby with me.
Marie will pick up
Walter Jr. from school.
You'll have the house
to yourself for two days.
I want you to pack
your things and leave.
Why would I do that?
Hank has offered to help
since you shouldn't be doing
any heavy lifting.
Skyler.
I want you gone
by Monday morning, I want--
I want you gone.
Okay.
Can you at least tell me why?
Because you're a liar, Walt.
Two cell phones, after all.
What?
Right before your surgery,
I asked if you had packed
your cell phone,
and you said, "Which one?"
When?
Skyler, I was medicated.
I mean, I-I-I could have
said the world was flat.
You know what I think?
I think you accidentally
told the truth.
Honey, we have been over this.
Asked and answered, right?
Then it got me thinking again,
about all the strange behavior.
Not the least of which
was the disappearance.
Out of my mind with worry,
calling hospitals,
checking the morgue.
Your fugue state?
I had to believe that, didn't I?
I had to find a way.
I mean, who would lie
about such a thing?
You tell me, Skyler.
You tell me exactly what
it is you think I'm lying about.
[CHUCKLES]
What? An affair?
I'm having an affair.
Is that what you think?
That's what I was thinking.
Yeah. For the last few weeks.
With whom?
Who am I having an affair with?
Well, my guess
was Gretchen Schwartz.
Something was going on
between you. I just knew.
Jesus. Skyler.
Get me a Bible to swear on,
if that's what it takes.
I am not having an affair
with Gretchen.
Oh, I know. I know you're not.
Because I asked her.
It really took me forever
to get in touch with her.
She was ducking
my calls for weeks.
So I finally left a message:
"What exactly is going on
between you and my husband?"
I thought that'd get
her attention and it did.
So she called me back,
and she finally told me.
The money for your treatment,
Gretchen and Elliott
didn't give you a dime.
They paid for nothing.
You refused every offer
they made you.
But that didn't make sense,
because I checked with
Delcavoli and the hospital,
and-and not including
your surgery,
we're nearly paid up.
Over $100,000.
Out of where?
Out of thin air?
But then,
[WHISPERING]
I called your mother.
Yeah. Oh.
Thanks for that too.
But I thought, you know,
maybe she has some money
that I don't know about.
Maybe she contributed.
[SIGHS]
It's possible.
It-It turns out that not only
is the money
not from your mother,
she didn't even know
that you have cancer.
You never went to see her.
I-I-I dropped you
at the airport.
I picked you up.
You were gone for four days,
and yet she swears
that you were never there.
Lies on top of lies
on top of lies.
Skyler.
Could you,
just once,
do me the courtesy
of not denying it?
Skyler.
Skyler, don't do this, please.
I-- I--
Skyler, please don't go.
[PANTING]
If I tell you the truth,
will you stay?
Stay, and I will
tell you everything.
Whatever it is,
I'm afraid to know.
[ENGINE STARTS]
DONALD:
Wayfarer-515, radio check.
Wayfarer-515,
Albuquerque Center, roger.
Climb and maintain 13,000.
Juliet-Mike-21,
squawk 4201, ident.
climb and maintain 17,000.
Clear direct to Albuquerque
via the--
Aircraft calling,
please stand by.
Jane-Mike-21, turn, heading--
Disregard.
Aircraft calling, say again.
Lifeguard-46,
clear direct Albuquerque,
climb and maintain 17,000.
Juliet-Mike-21, turn left,
heading 115.
Wayfarer-515,
traffic 3 o'clock, KingAir,
turn left, heading 085.
Sierra-alpha-alpha,
contact Albuquerque Center,
134.6.
Contact Albuquerque Center,
[BEEPING]
[HUMMING]
Wayfarer-515, descend to 10,000.
Juliet-Mike-21, do you have
that traffic at your 9 o'clock?
Wayfarer-515,
do you have that traffic?
[HUMMING]
[EXPLOSION]
[♪♪♪]