[LIGHTER CLICKS]
TORTUGA [IN SPANISH]:
More.
Another.
[IN SPANISH]
Careful, señor.
Hot day like today,
too much oil in the machine
can cause it to blow a gasket.
There are two kinds of men
in this world.
Those who drink
and those who pour.
Shut up and fill my glass.
Hey, you two.
Yes, you.
I used to be
just like you.
Worked dirt for the man
till my hands bled.
But no more.
Because I learned that a man
can never drink his fill
by waiting in line
for the tap.
MAN [IN SPANISH]:
Listen to him.
He can teach you
something.
Hey, how you doing, boss?
BOLSA:
Good to see you, my friend.
You know, I never pegged you
for such a deep thinker.
I keep thinking
I should write a book.
Maybe, maybe...
So, what brings you to this
burro's asshole of a town?
I knew I would
find you here.
Don't you have something
to deliver?
Cutting it close,
aren't you?
Ah, lots of time.
Tortuga may be slow
out of the gate, but he always--
Finishes first.
[LAUGHS]
Yes, I know.
Just like your namesake.
I like the way you talk,
Tortuga.
Yeah?
You've got such a way
with words.
They flow
like a waterfall.
I like that about you.
Salud.
I'm so stupid.
I missed your birthday.
No, I feel terrible.
So bad I came all the way here
to this burro's asshole
to give you your present.
Present?
Come on, no need
to go through the trouble.
Forget it, I wanted to.
I have it for you in the back.
Back there?
Yes. Come. Follow me.
It's perfect!
BOLSA:
Do you really like it?
Oh.
I love it!
What a great pet
it will make.
Thank you, boss!
Excellent.
Let me sign it for you.
Let me sign it...
"For the big talker."
[SCREAMING]
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
He's still breathing.
Well, by the looks of him, he
has no idea how close he came.
I'm assuming Saul Goodman
doesn't need to know.
Mum's the word.
[ENGINE STARTS]
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm
E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ And on this farm
He had a duck ♪
♪ E-I-E-I-O ♪
♪ With a quack, quack here
And a quack, quack there ♪
[SINGING OFF-KEY]
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm
E-I-E-I-O ♪
[HUMMING]
♪ Old MacDonald had a farm
E-I-E-I-O ♪
SKYLER:
Oh, son of a bitch.
Hang on, baby.
[DIALING]
[PHONE LINE RINGING]
WALT [OVER PHONE]:
Hello.
Walt? Are you in the house?
Oh, hey, Skyler.
Yeah, it's me.
What? What the hell
are you doing in there?
I'm back.
No, no, you're not back, Walt.
You're not back.
Get-- Get out of there.
Well, it's-- It's my house too,
Skyler.
I'm staying.
End of story.
We had an agreement.
I didn't agree to anything.
Now, look, just come on inside
and we'll talk this through,
okay?
No. No.
There's nothing to talk about.
I am not coming in there
until you get out.
Well, suit yourself.
SKYLER:
Walt.
Walt?
[SIGHS]
SKYLER:
What is wrong with you?
Skyler, I have
every right to be here.
No, you don't.
You don't live here anymore.
We're getting a divorce.
I don't agree to a divorce.
Well, it's not up to you.
If you don't get out of here
right now,
I'm gonna call the police
and I'm going to tell them
everything.
I mean it, Walt.
There's the phone.
[CRYING]
SKYLER:
It's ringing.
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]:
Albuquerque Police Department.
Operator number 314.
How may I help you?
Albuquerque Police Department.
Yes, I, uh-- I want to report
a disturbance, please.
No, no, it's not--
It's not exactly, it's, um...
It's a domestic issue.
Okay.
They're connecting me.
Right hand to God,
I will tell them.
Do what you have to do,
Skyler.
This family
is everything to me.
Without it,
I have nothing to lose.
Fine.
Yes. My name is Skyler White.
I need police assistance
at my home right away.
My soon-to-be-ex-husband
broke into my house,
and I need an officer
to come and remove him.
It's 308 Negra Arroyo Lane.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you.
They're coming.
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
Dad's here?
WALT: Great, he's home.
WALT JR.: Dad.
Hey, son.
How are you? Oh!
Are-- Are you back
for good?
Why are you home
so soon?
I-- I'm not.
Ah.
Hey, I am starving.
How about a grilled cheese?
Yeah, sure.
You want one too?
Walter,
your dad and I
have something
we need to discuss.
When your sandwich is ready,
I'll bring it to your room.
Mom, ca-can't it wait?
I haven't seen Dad in,
like, forever.
Walter?
WALT: How was school?
WALT JR.: It was good.
WALT: Yeah? Homework?
WALT JR.:
No, not really.
WALT:
What does that mean?
[WALT LAUGHS]
Mmm.
So are you gonna be
at work tomorrow?
WALT:
Yeah, that's the plan.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hello, ma'am. We were called
about a disturbance?
It's more of a trespassing
situation, really, but...
Yeah, that was me.
You called the cops on Dad?
SKYLER:
I came home from work,
and he was back.
He had just moved back
into the house.
And I asked him to leave,
but he won't listen. I just...
I want him out.
I want him out of the house.
Okay, Mrs. White,
there's a couple questions
I need to ask you.
It's important
you answer honestly.
Did he strike you?
No.
Has he ever hit you?
This is not about violence.
This is about trespassing.
About him being here
against my will.
Okay. Trespassing.
You're divorced, then?
No, working on it. Um...
Right now,
were separated.
Legally separated?
Well, there's not a court order,
if that's what you mean.
But we've been living apart
for almost two weeks,
give or take.
I-I changed the locks.
Isn't that breaking
and entering?
Whose name is on the title?
Both of us.
It's-- It's jointly owned.
We can't arrest a man for
breaking into his own house.
Not without a court order
requiring he stays away.
Unless he's threatened
you or the kids.
No. Not--
[HOLLY CRYING]
Not physically.
But having him
in the house is just...
It's-- It's not a good thing.
Excuse me.
I got her, honey.
Come here.
Here we go.
You hungry? You hungry?
Oh. That was it.
I'm sorry, officer.
Where were we?
COP:
Disagreements.
Yes, well,
we've had our share of that.
I haven't...
I haven't been the most
attentive husband lately.
Mrs. White,
would this be easier
if we stepped outside
for a minute?
No.
Nope.
I'm fine right here.
I'm gonna level with you,
ma'am.
If you want him
out of the house,
you'll have to help me.
Is it possible maybe he's broken
any laws that you know of?
Anything at all.
Anything that we can work
with here, just tell me.
Even if it's just a suspicion,
I can work with that.
I'll get him out of the house
for you.
COP:
What's your take on all this?
WALT JR.:
It's my mom's fault.
She won't even say
what my dad did
and it's because
he didn't do anything.
I don't know why
she's being this way.
My dad, he is a great guy.
WALT:
Son, it's not your mom's fault.
Mrs. White.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
There's no legal basis
for us to remove your husband
from the house.
Next time you feel things
are getting out of control,
you should call this number.
It's the family hotline.
I'd really look into
some counseling.
Best of luck to you folks.
Listen, thank you, officers.
We're sorry.
Why you gotta--? Why you gotta
do this to Dad?
Junior, wait,
come on.
Don't blame your mother
for this.
[DOOR SLAMS]
Sorry.
[SHUSHING]
[HOLLY CRYING]
Welcome home.
[PHONE DIALING]
[DOORBELL RINGING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
He lives.
Happy housewarming, kid.
Don't look so glad to see me.
Thanks.
Oh, interesting decor.
It's, uh, subtle.
The whole minimalist thing
never really blew my hair back,
but hey.
So how are you doing?
Staying clean?
Good. I was kind of worried
that you were back to old habits
since I didn't hear from you,
you know.
You realize
how stupid it is
to ignore your counsel's
phone calls?
What if I was trying
to warn you
the DEA was gonna kick down
your door? What then?
Why don't you spare me
the sermon
and get to why
you're here?
Fair enough.
Remember the other day
when I brought up the idea
of you getting back in touch
with your, uh, partner?
Well, I kind of wanted
to re-float that boat.
I'm not suggesting you
yourself get back to cooking.
I mean, you being
in rehab and all.
I only want you to convince
the master chef to do his thing.
So, what do you say?
Sure, man. Whatever.
Okay. Whatever what?
I mean,
you gonna call him?
I said I'll handle it.
Now, bounce, will you?
Please?
Final thought.
Look at this place.
You're house-poor,
you got no bankroll.
If you get
the maestro cooking again,
I'll make it
worth your while.
[SIGHS]
Call him.
[DIALS]
JANE [ON RECORDING]:
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
[HANK SIGHS]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Schrader.
Yes, sir. Yeah, what's up?
Yeah?
[LAUGHS]
That's great news, sir.
Thank you.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely,
you can bet on that.
Hey, listen,
thanks again, sir,
I really appreciate you stepping
to the plate. Thank you.
[LAUGHING]
So you gonna keep me
in suspense or what?
What's the good news?
Merkert called in
a couple favors.
El Paso wants me back. Ahh.
Hey, man, congrats, man.
That's fantastic.
Thank you.
Yeah.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR ALARM BEEPS]
[♪♪♪]
Hello.
[ALL CLUCKING AND PEEPING]
[♪♪♪]
[BELL DINGS]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
GUS [IN SPANISH]:
Gentlemen. Welcome.
Thank you for coming.
Any difficulty
at the border?
The day I can't get
across the border
is the day I retire.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Please, come in.
I apologize that it's not
wheelchair accessible.
BOLSA:
My apologies, Gustavo.
Of course,
you should have been advised.
It's your territory, you had
a right to bless the order.
But...
We had no reason to believe
the man was of concern to you.
Indeed, he is.
So you're in business
with this Heisenberg.
I don't know him by that name,
but yes.
I've made no secret
of the fact that
I have always
done business
with certain local
manufacturers.
You and I, we still
make money together.
It's never affected
our relationship.
Don Salamanca
had a nephew named Tuco.
Yes, I knew of him.
BOLSA:
Then perhaps you know
Don Salamanca mentored him
in the business.
Thought of Tuco as a son.
When Don Salamanca
was no longer able,
Tuco took over
for his uncle.
He was a key man
in our organization
north of the border.
He was loyal.
This Heisenberg,
Walter White,
he was one of Tuco's
local suppliers.
Until he betrayed Tuco.
So now you see,
blood must be repaid by blood.
Tuco's cousins here,
they have the right
to exact vengeance.
The Salamanca family,
the cartel,
stands shoulder to shoulder.
[BELL DINGS]
Don Salamanca.
Gentlemen.
I feel your loss deeply.
Please accept
my condolences.
I have no issue with
your right to vengeance.
But I am presently engaged
in business with this man.
When our business is done,
he will no longer be
of any concern to me.
Until then...
I need him alive.
[BELL DINGING RAPIDLY]
Excuse us.
I don't tell you how to fry
your chickens, Gustavo.
You should leave matters of my
organization's politics to me.
Do I not run
my own territory?
Of course you do.
And I will advise them
to be patient.
But I recommend you finish your
business with the man quickly.
Or you risk losing the
good graces of the cartel.
That would not be wise.
And those boys inside,
I cannot guarantee
that they will listen.
They are not like you and I.
[DIALS]
JANE [ON RECORDING]:
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
[♪♪♪]
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words....
[SIGHS]
[HOLLY CRYING]
Oh, sweetheart.
Sweetie, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's okay.
It's okay, my girl.
Yes, it's okay. It's okay.
Mama's got you.
Oh, I've got you.
Yes. Yes.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
WALT:
Skyler? Want some help?
Skyler, can I use
the bathroom?
[SNIFFING]
God--
[URINE TRICKLING]
WOMAN:
What do you mean?
Against your will?
SKYLER:
Yes. Very much against my will.
He just--
He showed right back up.
And he doesn't want a divorce.
Won't even consider it.
I called the police on him.
I was-- I was so clo--
So close to what?
Nothing. Never mind.
Skyler, I can't
advise you properly
if you don't give me
all the facts.
Understand, I'm bound by
the attorney-client privilege
to keep everything
you tell me a secret.
I can't tell a soul
unless you authorize me to.
Even if it's
something illegal?
Especially if it's illegal.
I'm your lawyer, not the police.
My job is to protect you.
[WHISPERING]
My husband makes meth.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Methamphetamine.
Your husband's
a drug dealer?
He's a manufacturer,
technically.
They, um...
They call them cooks.
I looked it up
on the Internet.
This is my advice,
and you should take it:
Sue your husband for divorce
immediately.
Let me go to the police and tell
them what you just told me.
I'll go in ex parte
to get a restraining order
from the court today.
If he comes anywhere
near you and your children,
he'll go straight to jail
no questions asked.
This is a no-brainer.
It's the best thing for you
and your family.
I can't.
I can't do it.
I don't want my son
to find out
that his father
is a criminal.
I just...
I can't do that to him.
In the end,
it may not be up to you.
Drug dealers have a way
of getting caught.
Walt has lung cancer.
His treatment
bought him some time.
But the doctors, they all say
that sooner or later...
I can't see why I should
lay all this on my family
when things may...
resolve themselves
on their own
without anyone else knowing.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Man, did I lose a bet
or something?
What are we doing
in this shithole?
Just relax, will you?
GOMEZ: Relax?
This is the kind of place
you get knifed.
We should have went
to Chili's, man.
All right, already. Jesus.
GOMEZ: Outback Steakhouse.
It's not too late.
They got that Blooming Onion.
What's wrong with
spicing things up a little?
This spice looks like
it's been through
a couple of guys already.
So when you headed
back down to El Paso?
Uh, you know. Between
all the packing, errands,
getting my ducks in a row,
maybe a week or two.
Week or two?
Come on, man.
I'd be dying to get
back in.
Not like there's nothing going
on up here.
What are you talking about?
Ain't jack going on up here.
It's quiet as hell.
I'm gonna hit the head.
[♪♪♪]
Those two over there.
I think they're holding.
Man, in this place, the
bartender's probably holding.
All right.
Whoa, whoa. What you doing?
Calling A.P.D.,
what do you think?
Since when can't we handle
a couple dirtballs?
Come on. Courtesy call.
What if Vice is running
some kind of undercover op?
Screw it.
It's your turn to pay.
[♪♪♪]
Where you going?
Gotta take a leak.
Jesus, get yourself
some Flomax.
♪ I said Lord
Take me downtown ♪
♪ I'm just looking
For some tush ♪
♪ I've been bad
I've been good ♪
Stand up.
♪ I ain't asking for much ♪
MAN:
You got a problem
with us, bitch?
Your move.
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
DEA. Don't move.
Go out and tell my partner
to get his ass in here.
♪ Take me back
Way back home ♪
♪ Not by myself ♪
[DIALS]
JANE [ON RECORDING]:
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words:
"Do Not Call list."
However, if you're cool,
leave it at the beep.
If you're trying to sell me
something, four words:
"Do Not Call--"
[PHONE BEEPS]
[PHONE LINE RINGING]
[PHONE LINE BEEPING]
RECORDING [ON PHONE]:
The number you have reached,
149-4985,
in area code 505 is no longer--
[♪♪♪]
[FRONT DOOR OPENS
THEN CLOSES]
[GARAGE DOOR OPENS]
[SIGHS]
[GARAGE DOOR CLOSES]
WALT:
Skyler.
Can we talk?
ASAC wants to see you.
And?
We were hanging back,
we saw a deal go down.
I went outside
to call it in.
You stayed to keep an eye
on the suspects.
That's when
they attacked you.
What I didn't tell him is that
you left your gun under the seat
before you went back inside.
WALT:
I've done a terrible thing.
But I did it
for a good reason.
I did it for us.
That is college tuition
for Walter Jr.
and Holly 18 years
down the road.
That is health insurance
for you and the kids.
For Junior's physical therapy,
his SAT tutor.
It's money
for groceries,
for gas,
for birthdays
and graduation parties.
Skyler, that money is for
this roof over your head,
the mortgage that you are not
going to be able to afford
on a part-time bookkeeper's
salary when I'm gone.
Walt, I--
Please. Please.
This money,
I didn't steal it.
It doesn't belong
to anyone else.
I earned it.
The things I've done
to earn it...
the things that
I've had to do...
I've got to live with them.
Skyler...
all that I've done,
all the sacrifices that I have
made for this family,
all of it
will be for nothing
if you don't accept
what I've earned.
Please.
I'll be here when you
get home from work.
You can give me
your answer then.
Hey, Sky.
[SIGHS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Hey, some coffee?
Yeah.
That report's looking real good.
I like how it looks.
Good.
Are your kids home?
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SIGHS]
Ooh. Ooh, ooh.
It's here! It's here!
Everybody, come on in! Look!
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Mrs. White.
Oh.
Hey, Louis.
Hey, uh, thanks for having me
over for dinner.
Um, sure.
Hey, Skyler.
I'm, uh, cooking dinner.
Pot roast.
Uh, could you...?
So how was your day?
Good.
Excellent.
I hope you don't mind,
I invited Louis to stay
for dinner tonight.
You know, as a thank-you
for driving Walter Jr.
to school for us.
We've been kind of absent,
but, I tell you,
Louis really pitched in.
Um...
Look, I just wanna say
that I feel good about
our talk this morning,
and I'm very eager to hear
what you're thinking about,
about what we talked about.
But, you know, whenever
you're ready, of course.
[SIGHS THEN CHUCKLES]
Honesty is good.
Don't you think?
I fucked Ted.
SKYLER:
Boys, dinner.
Iced tea?
WALT JR.: Yeah.
SKYLER: Louis?
WALT JR.: Thank you.
LOUIS: Yes, please.
SKYLER: All right.
I want you boys both
to eat your salad, okay?
WALT JR.:
Really?
SKYLER:
I know nobody likes salad,
but it's good for you.
Thanks, darling.
WALT JR.: Thank you.
[♪♪♪]