So cigarettes and gas is $79.70.
Crap.
There's an ATM
right outside.
Yeah, I don't have a card.
Well, you can write
a personal check with ID.
Kind of in between banks
right now.
You think I could just
come back later?
I'm totally good for it.
I'd come back, I swear.
If it were me, I'd be totally,
you know, "No problem."
But my dad is this
ginormous hard-ass.
He was in Fallujah
for a year.
And he always checks
the receipts.
I mean, like, always.
I gotta call him. I'm sorry.
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold on a second.
Maybe we could...
trade.
Ever try it?
I mean, I smoke pot
a lot sometimes.
I party.
But...
But that stuff's really
addictive, right?
Not really. It's just
a media thing. You know?
What's it like?
It's awesome.
Everything's maximum
interesting.
You get these really cold and
sharp-like action
dagger feelings.
It's awesome.
Come on.
What do you say?
[DOOR BEEPING]
Have a nice day.
[♪♪♪]
SAUL:
So how does it feel?
Does it hurt?
Yeah, it's tight.
SAUL:
Yeah, but is it painful?
It's hard to breathe.
Well, you need your breathing.
Heh, heh.
Although let's not
lose sight of the fact
that you were the victim
of a terrible accident, Antonio,
so some discomfort
is to be expected.
["BATTLE HYMN OF THE REPUBLIC"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Let's go with that one.
[SAUL SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
A cashier's check, por favor.
Oh, and spread the word.
I'm building a class-action,
flight 515.
Victims' families
would be great.
I'll take anyone on the ground
who suffered emotionally.
Anxiety, sleeplessness.
You get the picture.
Trouble?
WALT [ON RECORDING]:
Ted Beneke?
You cannot be serious.
That guy is a joke.
SKYLER: You called my bluff.
WALT:
What does that mean?
SKYLER:
You dared me to tell the police
and I couldn't do it,
so you win.
If you want to stay
in this house, fine,
but we are not married anymore.
WALT:
I told you that I was done
cooking meth, Skyler.
I promised you that.
SKYLER: So what?
WALT:
At least I didn't run off
to go--
Jesus! I mean, everything
that I did,
I did for this family.
SKYLER:
Just keep telling
yourself that.
WALT:
What's that mean?
SKYLER:
You don't like it, then leave.
And take your drug money.
WALT:
That's what you want.
[LOUD WHIRRING ON RECORDING]
Jesus.
Garbage disposal.
WALT:
You think this will get me
to move out?
You can screw Ted,
you can screw
the butcher, the mailman.
Whoever you want.
Screw them all.
I'm not going anywhere.
SKYLER:
Suit yourself.
[DOOR SLAMS ON RECORDING]
Is this a good
or bad thing?
WALT:
Suit myself.
You want me to suit myself?
I'll suit myself to his face!
It's a bad thing.
Hello.
Walter White
to see Ted Beneke.
I'm sorry. Mr. Beneke's
on a conference call.
Mm. Hmm. Okay.
I will wait.
It could be
a while.
I have all the time
in the world.
Okay.
[CHUCKLES]
Here we go. Okay.
Excuse me.
Mr. Beneke's not available.
Ted? Come on.
RECEPTIONIST:
Sir, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Ted, I can see you.
I can see you standing
right there in your office.
Now, come on.
Open the door.
Come on, let's talk.
I just want to talk.
That's all.
Come on, let's be men about
this. Okay? How about that?
Aha.
Hey, Walt. I'm kind of
in the middle of something now.
Oh, yes, you are.
So open the door.
You're damn right.
You're right in the middle.
Just open the door
and let's talk about it, okay?
Open the door, Ted, right now.
You don't want to be a man
about it?
Plan B. How do you like that?
Plan B.
RECEPTIONIST:
We have a situation.
Walt. Walt. Walt.
What are you doing?
I'm talking with Ted.
Next time, you'll open the door.
MAN: Freeze! Come on.
WALT: Oh, damn it.
No, I'm just here to talk.
I just want to talk to him.
MAN:
Outside. Let's go.
WALT:
God. Can I just talk?
I just want to talk to him.
Calm down.
I'm just-- Okay, all right.
All right, all right, all right.
I'm calm. I'm calm.
MAN:
Asshole.
Ow!
What do you want?
Hey! Hey, come on.
What the hell is wrong with you?
You act like you're the first
guy this happened to.
I caught my second wife
screwing my stepdad, okay?
It's a cruel world, Walt.
Grow up.
I just wanted to
talk to him.
Yeah, well, now
I'm talking to you.
Consider this
an intervention.
You could have been arrested
back there. You understand.
Speaking as your lawyer,
I'm always looking
for billable hours.
But speaking as
your business associate,
I'm strongly advising
that you get your shit together.
Just cool it with this Beneke
guy, at least for now. Okay?
Let's talk shop, because I think
this is a great opportunity
to channel some of that negative
energy into something positive.
How did you know?
Sorry?
About Skyler. About where
to find me just now.
How did you know?
That's just my meticulousness.
Don't bog down in detail, Walt.
The lesson here should be--
Did you bug my house?
[SCOFFS]
Yeah, but I didn't know
it was your house, did I?
You'd moved out. Besides,
you basically told me to.
I told you to?
You strongly hinted
that I should.
You were worried your wife might
say something to the police.
What? No, no, that's not true.
When the hell did I say that?
Let's not get lost in the who,
what and whens.
The point is we did our due
diligence and she didn't talk.
She kept quiet.
She stood by you, Walt,
which, if you ask me, is the
ironical silver lining here.
I mean, on the one hand,
sure, she snuck off
the reservation
to get some dirty,
damp and deep.
On the other hand--
[GRUNTING]
Off me.
You're fired!
You're done!
SAUL: Good!
"Oh, boohoo,
I won't cook meth anymore."
You're a crybaby.
Who needs you?
I'm unplugging the website,
so no more money laundering.
How do you like that?
I want those bugs
out of my house today.
I want them out now!
You just bought
a $300 suit, psycho!
Go.
Great, drilled right
into the stucco.
Oh.
A little bit of putty,
you'll be fine.
Just make sure you get
all of those things.
A, these things
cost $800 apiece.
B, you're not that interesting.
So yeah, I'll get
all of them, Walter.
Great line of work,
by the way.
Real upstanding field.
Yeah, well,
I enjoy it.
You're free to leave now.
Anytime.
You know, Walter,
sometimes it doesn't hurt to
have someone watching your back.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[♪♪♪]
CARMEN:
Mr. White?
Hi.
What's up?
CARMEN:
I can't begin to understand
what you're going through, Walt,
with all of
your health concerns
and the stresses
you've been under.
But still, as educators,
there are certain
responsibilities
we need to be
meeting here
to the school
and to the students themselves.
Of course.
Is this a Wheaten Terrier?
Uh... Norfolk.
Norfolk?
That's surprising.
Walt, could you come back over
here and have a seat, please?
Sure.
You've been absent
a lot recently.
And when you are here
at school,
there have been
some behavioral questions.
And frankly I'm concerned.
Thank you.
Are you feeling okay?
Do you think maybe
I should call Skyler?
Um...
No.
Let's just keep this...
What--?
Hey!
Walt, what's wrong with you?
[WOMAN ON PA
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
You know, look,
you're the one
always talking
about D.C., okay?
This is how you get there.
You answer the bell.
You pay your dues.
Besides, you know, it's a big
deal to get picked for this.
El Paso's like the Super Bowl.
I could get killed
crossing the street, okay?
Whatever. You know,
I want to go.
What about last time?
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Schrader.
Hey, sheriff. Yeah.
Blue, huh?
Yeah, yeah. Thing is--
Thing is I'm supposed to be
getting on a plane right now.
The stuff this guy had was blue.
You sure about that?
Yeah.
Yeah, I want to talk to him.
Taxi.
[HORN HONKS]
Hi.
Man, I'm sorry.
I needed to talk to you, but
you weren't at your apartment.
No, I moved back home.
That's good, right?
Yeah.
Yo, did you just get fired?
No.
No, no, no.
It's more like a sabbatical.
Indefinite. Yeah.
So, what's up?
Should we go somewhere?
No, this is fine.
So I want an intro
to your guy.
What guy?
Your guy. Your distribution guy.
The guy Saul hooked you up with.
No, no, no. Come on, Jesse.
I thought about it...
God.
...and I want to.
It's the one thing
I'm good at.
No, that is just not true.
You're good at a lot of things,
son.
Like what?
What about your sobriety?
I told you,
I'm not using.
Ever.
I just want back
into the business.
Well, I don't. I'm sorry.
I know, and that's cool.
I'm not asking you to cook.
What's this?
In the end, I just went
with two reflux condensers.
I didn't want to lose track
of my pH levels.
But I did everything else
just like you taught me.
Super careful in my amounts
and watched the numbers
every step of the way.
So, what do you think?
It's good, right?
What in the hell is this?
What?
This. This.
This is my product.
This is my formula.
This is mine.
It's our product, but yeah,
I was gonna cut you in.
Oh, you were gonna cut me in?
No, no, no. I cut you in.
What the hell
is your problem?
All I'm asking is
for you to set a meet.
Absolutely not.
Why?
Because I am not gonna lend
my name to an inferior product.
I mean,
look at the diameters here.
What did you use
for reduction?
Don't tell me.
Platinum dioxide, right?
No. Mercury-aluminum
amalgam.
The dioxide's too hard
to keep wet.
All right, well,
you must've done it wrong, then.
Your color is all cloudy,
so you were struggling
with distillation too.
Now, this is very shoddy work,
Pinkman.
I'm actually embarrassed
for you.
What?
No way.
I gave out samples
and everyone said
it was the bomb.
[SCOFFS]
Oh, they said it was the bomb.
And who were they, I wonder?
A bunch of meth heads?
Yeah.
They should know, right?
Yeah, well, sorry.
I can't help you.
Fine, ass-wad.
I'll contact the guy myself.
Oh, yeah? Well, good luck.
Because my guy is a pro and
he doesn't deal with junkies.
You know what? Eat me.
Anytime, loser.
Hey, hey, hey!
Wait. Hey!
[♪♪♪]
I can't believe
it's only 4:00.
This day is dragging.
[WHISPERING]
Okay.
[SKYLER MOANING]
I wish I could stay.
TED:
So stay.
What's stopping you?
Heh, heh. What,
like everything, you mean?
How about my lunatic husband
refusing to leave the house?
[CLEARS THROAT]
So move in here.
And then my son
hating me even more.
That'll pass. I went
through that with the girls.
They adapt.
And now everyone
at work thinks
I'm an evil
ladder-climbing whore.
They're all fired,
effective immediately.
What else?
Heh, heh, heh.
Oh, aren't you the answer man?
Where did it, um--? Ahem.
Where did it go wrong, exactly,
with you and Walt?
I mean, I always saw him
as kind of...
mild-mannered.
Something, I don't know,
change when he got sick or...?
I don't know what changed, Ted.
And I just don't feel really
comfortable talking about it.
Sorry.
Just asking out of
self-interest.
Gotta make sure I don't make
the same mistake.
I would be amazed.
Just let me see if
I'm following you here, Russell.
You got this stuff
from some guy at Gasparza's
who was wearing tan pants
and who you're 80 percent sure
had a mustache.
That's it, right?
That's your brain
working at maximum capacity?
[GRUNTING AND PANTING]
Russell.
Everything all right
in there?
Mel. The dude's name was Mel.
Well, there
you go. See?
You served an actual
earthly function.
I can't believe
I remembered that.
Mel who?
Does he have a last name?
Yeah, uh, Mel.
Wait.
Was it Mel
or Mark?
It was definitely an M name.
Oh, man, I'm losing it.
Wait, wait.
Yeah.
It's gone.
It was an M name though.
Yeah.
I remember the "muh" sound.
All right, well, we'll go
with the "muh" sound.
Thanks a lot. Appreciate it.
Yeah.
He definitely had tan pants.
Remind me to get a vasectomy.
Okay, it's after 9, so this bar
that Girl George is at,
probably wall-to-wall dirtbags
by now.
Let's go have a little
looky-loo,
see if we can't find
this M-named clown.
What? It's a lead.
Lead to what?
To Heisenberg.
I told you it was
only a matter of time
before this guy booted
up again.
Here we go, my friend.
Don't hate me because
I'm beautiful, Gomey.
Just apologize and
buy me a beer.
Man, you're
reaching.
This stuff could be a knockoff
or left over from an older cook.
How do you know Heisenberg's
gearing up again?
How do I know?
Because I know.
I don't get it.
This is the reason why you're
blowing off the task force?
Chase down teeners?
I'm getting tired
of all the second-guessing.
If you're not sufficiently
stimulated
by this investigation,
do us both a favor
and ask for a transfer.
What is up with you lately?
Starting bar fights,
turning down El Paso,
and now this bullshit?
Do you need to talk
to someone or what?
Talk to someone?
Talk to who?
I'm not trying to step
on your toes, bro. Okay?
I'm just worried about you.
That's all.
Appreciate that, bro.
Now take your hand off
my shoulder.
Yeah, yeah,
the one that was on TV.
Did any little piece
fall on your property?
I'm not looking for
an entire wing here, Mr. Linkas.
It could be a nut or a bolt.
It could be a bag of peanuts,
just so long as it caused you
pain and suffering.
Oh, no, no, no. Closed.
Calling you back.
You had your chance. I told you
to get him cooking again.
You blew it off
and now it's too late.
The guy's gone
mass maniac on us!
All I wanted was to show
you two your potential.
And what do I get in return?
A bone contusion.
You wanna see the scar?
I wish you two had--
Hi, there.
How in the hell did you
get Walt to--?
I made it.
You know the guy
who knows the guy, right?
Well, good news is
for a stage-three cancer,
the guy's doing well physically.
Mentally, the guy's a disaster.
He's gone off the rails
over this thing with his wife.
My opinion, he's not coming
back. Not on his own.
Your friends were at his place
again, by the way.
They drew something on the
street outside his house.
The scythe.
Animals.
Does the lawyer know?
Should he?
No.
If you want this guy to produce
again, why not just tell him?
You stand between him
and an ax in the head.
I don't believe fear to be
an effective motivator.
I want investment.
For now, I'm simply interested
in time frame.
He will live for
the foreseeable future, yes?
Foreseeable.
Couple years at least,
barring acts of God
and men with axes.
Oh.
From the lawyer,
I'm supposed to let you know
the Pinkman kid
is looking to sell.
I don't work with junkies.
That's what I thought you'd say.
Probably for the best.
What I hear, he and Walter
are splitsville.
Really?
That's what Goodman says.
Cats and dogs.
Do the deal.
Mm.
Hmm.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
[CELL PHONE BEEPING]
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]:
You have one unheard message.
MAN [ON RECORDING]:
Agent Schrader, you need
to be calling me back ASAP.
I've got Texas breathing down
my neck and I'm not about--
CARA:
No, I haven't seen Matt
since my dad fired him,
like, a while ago.
Where can I find him,
you think?
No idea. Haven't seen him.
I know. You said
that a few times.
Yeah, because I haven't
seen him.
I don't know what else to say.
What's your name, darling?
Cara.
Where did this come from,
Cara?
I-- I-- I don't know.
What is it? Drugs?
Look, I'm just gonna
come right out and say it.
You're a bad liar, Cara.
Don't get me wrong.
Not the worst I've ever seen.
Once had a guy try to explain
the dope balloon up his butt
on bad Thai food.
Still, you're not
a very good liar.
I honestly don't know--
Stop.
You look like a good kid. I'm
not here to get you in trouble.
But you need to tell me
where this came from right now!
I never do stuff like this.
I swear to God.
I tried it and I hated it,
so I just gave it to Matt.
Okay, and who gave it to you?
Some guy.
He came in a couple days ago
and wanted to trade it for gas.
Some guy?
What's his name?
Okay, what--?
What did he look like?
[CRYING]
I don't know.
He looked pretty normal.
You know, um, white.
I think his hair
was lightish brown.
He had really blue eyes.
They were really, really blue.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, dreamy.
Okay, what else?
Piercings, jewelry, distinctive
articles of clothing. Come on.
Come on.
Listen to me.
It's real important that I find
the person that had these drugs.
So if you can remember
anything else...
Come on, think.
Come on, now. Come on.
He drove an RV.
Okay, good, good.
What can you remember?
What kind of RV?
What color?
Did you spot a license plate?
I don't know the kinds,
and I didn't see the license.
But the color was, I think,
white, brownish color.
I'm sorry.
I know I'm not helping you...
but, please, don't tell my dad.
[SOBBING]
Cara.
Please, tell me that
that camera works.
Damn it.
[♪♪♪]
Bingo.
These eggs are good,
Mom.
Thanks.
WALT JR.:
Hey, you know what's weird?
Dad's website.
It's been three days
since the last donation.
Yeah, well,
people lose interest.
Um...
So how long
are you off for?
A few weeks.
I'll play it by ear.
I probably pushed it,
you know,
going back to work too soon.
Think I can get a ride today?
Louis has a doctor's
appointment.
Yeah.
Hey, so, Dad can
babysit now, right?
You won't have to take
Holly to work every day.
Sometime, maybe.
Yeah, we'll see.
[♪♪♪]
What's up?
I think you'll
seriously enjoy, yo.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Wait. No, no. No way.
Hey! Hey!
Hey. What the hell?
This is only half.
That's right.
It's your half.
Yo, where's
the other half, bitch?
I mean, the whole thing
was crazy.
Poor bastard.
I felt sorry for him.
I think he actually thought we
were the cable guys, you know.
Anyway, uh, sorry about
those missed calls, chief.
I'm changing providers.
It won't happen again.
Are you going to El Paso, Hank?
Hell, yes.
With pointy boots and bells on.
Got this break
in the Heisenberg case.
The blue meth, you mean?
The teenth?
Yeah, well, that teenth
got things rolling.
I traced it to a gas station
in Cibola.
That's where I got these.
The station's closed-circuit
was down-- Surprise, surprise.
--but I was able to pull
some of these snapshots off
an ATM security camera.
We always thought these guys
might be camper-cooking.
First off, your typical
Class C motor home
is gonna grunt at least 5000
pounds of interior fixtures.
Appliances, furniture,
built-ins,
5000 pounds at least, okay?
See how high
that suspension's riding?
No way, no how, this thing's
carrying that kind of weight.
This thing has been cleared out
and stripped down
to its tight-and-curlies.
For what? Blood bank?
Maybe a bookmobile?
There's no clear view
of the plates.
Yeah, well, you can only
get so lucky, right?
But there's no front plate.
Tells me it's likely
New Mexico registration.
I check with DMV.
There are only 29 of these
early-'80s Bounders
registered in the state.
Only 29?
Yeah.
So I gotta go, you know,
knock on some doors.
They need you in El Paso, Hank.
You bet. I'm just gonna wrap up
this Heisenberg thing first.
You're refusing the assignment.
I'm not. I'll go.
It's just
I need some more time.
You're not hearing me,
Agent Schrader.
You're out of time.
Are you going to El Paso now,
tonight?
It's a simple yes or no.
No. I can't.
But that's only
because I'm really close
to something big here.
Better get to it, then.
MAN [ON RADIO]:
This is KECA 480,
Albuquerque's news radio.
KECA news time, 10:13.
Our top story this hour,
Donald Margolis,
the air-traffic controller
criticized for his role
in the recent air disaster
in which 167 persons died,
was rushed to an area hospital
early this morning,
apparently the victim of
a self-inflicted gunshot wound.
Police won't say whether
or not--
[CHANGES STATION]
♪ All I took
Was just one look ♪
♪ It has just begun ♪
♪ The two of us are one ♪
♪ Spending all our days ♪
♪ In the Valley of the Sun ♪
♪ Here eyes were like
The velvet stars ♪
[MAN WHISTLES]
[GRUNTS]
Your half.
♪ All I took was
Just one look ♪
♪ I knew that this
Was really love ♪
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Okay, okay.
♪ The two of us are one ♪
♪ Spending all our days ♪
♪ In the Valley of the Sun ♪
[♪♪♪]