I am awake.
You are not how I remember you
from class.
I mean, like, not at all.
Dude, this isn't even 7 grand,
all right? My guy wants 85.
This is all the money I have
in the world.
You are a drug dealer.
Negotiate.
Buy the RV.
We start tomorrow.
[LUKE WALKER & DJ LOKI'S
"ALPACA" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[YELLS]
Work it, work it, baby.
Yo, this is sick, brother.
Totally. God.
Yo, Jesse, I got these two fine
ladies who wanna participate.
You got the funds?
JESSE: Oh, I got the funds. Hey.
Would you ladies like to meet
my fat stack?
[LAUGHING]
Get in here.
Come on.
Hey, yo, yo.
Yo, you got champagne?
None of that cheap stuff.
I want the expensive shit.
Don Pérignon.
It's 400 a bottle.
Oh, well, in that case,
I'll only have two.
Oh, and I want the tall,
skinny glasses.
I like those
That's what James Bond drinks.
Mofos, I'm all about that.
Yo, Jesse, man, I gotta ask.
Where did you get all
the cheddar?
Must be moving
mad volume.
It's funny. You wanna know
what's funny?
What's funny?
This old dude, he gave it to me.
What?
He gave it to me.
It's his entire
life savings.
What? Why?
Because he's a dumb-ass.
That's why.
Oh, God.
STRIPPER:
Whoo!
JESSE:
Yes! Whoo!
All right, living large,
players.
[TEDDYBEARS'
"ROCKET SCIENTIST" PLAYING]
♪ Get, get, get, get ♪
♪ I'm not a rocket scientist ♪
♪ I rock the house
And sign the tits ♪
♪ And that's it ♪
♪ Don't take no astrophysicist
To make your ass throw fits ♪
♪ Now sistas, kick it ♪
♪ I'm the robot Elvis
Rocking my bionic pelvis ♪
♪ I'm technotronic
Sipping gin and tonic ♪
♪ Like I'm selfish ♪
♪ I am the killer
Shaking up some old ♪
♪ Rock and roll fool ♪
♪ Them drum-machines
Ain't got no soul ♪
♪ I keep it cool ♪
♪ Like Eskimo chicks
On Discovery Channel ♪
♪ I'm hot like Telemundo chicas
On a solar panel ♪
♪ See me on Sesame Street ♪
♪ Coolin' in
A cold chillin tee ♪
♪ I slap you silly like ♪
♪ Hillbilly chicks
On daytime TV ♪
[GUYS LAUGHING]
JESSE:
Thank you. Yo, thank you.
Thank you.
That was...
[VOMITS]
Awesome, bro.
Later.
Oh, man.
Oh, I'm so dead.
I only got...
Oh, damn.
I only got like 1400.
Waffle House? Yeah.
No, man.
Supposed to use that dude's
money to buy an RV.
What do you want
with a RV for?
Because, like...
Never mind.
Jesus.
Now I gotta, like,
leave town or change
my identity or something.
Guy's blackmailing me.
He's got, like,
a criminal mind, yo.
RV, yeah?
I can hook you up, bro.
I can totally get you an RV.
No, I need it today. Now.
No problem. Let's go.
You're telling me
you can get me an RV?
For 1400,
at 6 in the morning?
[GROANS]
[DOGS BARKING]
Right on.
So do I need to sign
something?
No, it's, like,
a no-paperwork-type deal.
Pleasure doing
business with you.
[CLATTERING]
Come on,
we gotta bounce.
What?
For real, yo.
Get it out of here.
[RV ENGINE STARTS]
[CAR ALARM BLARING]
[♪♪♪]
[SHOWER RUNNING]
Ooh.
Oh, my God, I love this floor.
This feels fantastic.
Can you control the temperature?
TED:
Yeah. There should be a
switch right next to you there.
It's a thermostat.
[SIGHS]
Ted, this has gotta be
the most amazing
invention ever.
I know. Contractor
talked me into it.
Seemed kind of
extravagant, but...
I gotta tell you, once you
try it, you can't go back.
I can never find anything
in this Buick.
You know, you could leave
a few things here if you want.
[DANCE MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Why don't you go get your dad?
Sure.
[KNOCKS]
Hey, Dad.
Dad?
Yeah.
Mom's asking.
Wanna come to dinner?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
You're not listening to me.
I don't know.
JESSE:
Yeah, right,
like you don't know.
What did I just say?
Give me the phone. Give it.
Like you didn't make
some deal behind my back.
Correct. I did not.
I was sitting at a stoplight
minding my own business,
when the man-- The man...
The kid threw a bag of money
through my window.
Whatever, man.
You owe me that money.
Let me talk to him.
I owe you?
I owe you nothing.
And I will get to the bottom
of this. Trust me.
Trust you? Trust you?
That's a good one.
Yeah, that's what I'm gonna do.
You wanna talk about trust,
Jesse? Let's talk.
I told you not to cook
my formula,
and you went ahead
and did it anyway.
Because I never said
I wouldn't cook it,
because it ain't yours.
It's ours. Plural, bitch.
You did not have my permission.
All I know is I got
half the money I'm due
and you got the rest.
SAUL:
Escalating. You're escalating.
You know what? Escalate this.
My meth, my money!
I will be a one-man
glass factory.
I will rock that RV 24--
It's buttoned up tight.
Can't see a damn thing.
I ain't feeling it.
No smoke, no smell, no waste.
There's no cook.
Could be they're setting up.
I heard movement inside.
I say we call it a night,
come back with a search warrant.
I'm not letting this sucker
out of my sight.
There's gotta be a way.
There's gotta be a way...
Hey, hey, hey.
[♪♪♪]
GOMEZ:
What are you doing?
[SCREAMING]
GOMEZ:
No, no, no.
MAN:
What the hell are you
doing up there?
Are you some kind of a pervert?
MAN:
Yeah, because we were here
last year.
HANK:
Sorry. I appreciate...
Going after the bad guys.
I'm sorry and enjoy the rest
of your vacation. Okay?
Go back to your trailers.
Everything's okay.
Guy's VFW. He's cool.
We're gonna check out a couple
more and call it a morning.
Okay, what do you say?
Can't. Gotta get home.
Why, you leave your balls
in your wife's purse or what?
Gotta pack.
Where you headed?
Texas.
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]
[DOOR OPENS]
MARIE:
Hey there.
Hank?
[KNOCKS]
Can I come in?
HANK: Hey, babe.
MARIE: Hey.
How did it go last night?
Good.
Catch the bad guys?
Nope.
Want me to make you
some breakfast?
No. I'm, uh...
I'm heading back out after this.
Now? You worked
all night.
Get some sleep, Hank.
Those RVs aren't going anywhere.
They're recreational vehicles,
Marie. That's what they do.
You know what I mean.
I spoke with Blanca.
She said that Steven's
going to El Paso?
Yeah.
I was just wondering
how you feel about that.
I turned it down. End of story.
Good. Good.
Jesus, God knows
I'm relieved.
I needed some
time here
because I'm deep
into this investigation
and couldn't do both,
so I made a judgment call.
You know that you can talk to me
about things, right?
You don't have
to go through this alone.
Do you ask me which lead bib
to put on someone
before you nuke them?
Jesus, Marie.
I made a decision.
I'm not going through anything.
Doing my job.
I would like--
I know. I know.
A condo in Georgetown. I know.
If you would let me finish,
I was going to say
I'd like to be included.
That's all.
Don't you worry about my career.
My career is just fine.
Did you not wanna go?
I don't blame you.
I just--
Aren't you late for work
or something?
After what happened,
it would make perfect sense
for you to not
wanna go back.
I'm onto some important stuff
right here, now.
Mexico doesn't have
a damn thing to do with it.
Anyone who doubts that...
I mean, I'm doing
some actual good out here
and all I get are
these bullshit accusations!
What, everyone thinks
I'm jerking off on this thing?
Fine.
But I'm onto something.
I know it.
You understand me?
You hear me?
WALT:
What exactly is this?
I'll tell you
what I think it is.
A ploy.
A ploy to get me cooking again.
And an obvious one at that.
How do you mean?
As if I would seriously believe
you would hire an addict.
Jesse Pinkman?
Recovering or not.
You vouched for him previously.
I took you at your word.
No. No, no, no. Let me be clear.
Let me be perfectly clear.
Jesse was capable of working
under my supervision.
Trusting him
with a solo venture,
well, that's quite
another matter.
How he could possibly
produce anything
other than
a mediocre product at best.
I am told his product
was more or less consistent
with the quality
I had come to expect.
More or less?
More or less? Really?
Wow.
Boy, that is the...
Talk about setting the bar low.
Except you don't do that,
set the bar low.
Therefore, what conclusion
am I left to draw?
That you believe I have some
proprietary kind of selfishness
about my own formula.
Some sort of overweening
pride, I suppose,
that you think
simply overwhelms me,
clouds my judgment.
But it doesn't.
Absolutely not.
I simply respect the chemistry.
The chemistry must be respected.
I apologize for being
so transparent.
Would you take a drive with me?
I'd like to show you something.
[CAR APPROACHES]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hi. Is everything okay?
MARIE:
She's finished an entire bottle,
but she still seemed hungry.
She fell asleep.
I was thinking I'd give her
another when she wakes up.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely,
absolutely.
Fatten that baby up.
Will do.
Um...
Was that it?
So where are you?
Are you at work?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm at work.
I shouldn't be much longer.
Is that okay?
You know I love
my little pookums.
You can leave her with me
for the next 18 years
as far as I'm concerned.
Great. Thanks, Marie.
Are you sure you're okay?
Sweetie, what is it? Come on.
It's Hank.
Hank? What about him?
I don't know
how to talk to him.
I don't know what to say to him
anymore. I don't know how to...
Ever since El Paso,
ever since--
Maybe before...
Yeah. God knows he went
through a lot down there.
People blown up right in front
of him, blood everywhere,
and last week,
El Paso said they want him back.
Yeah?
He's not going. Steve Gomez
is going in his place,
and I don't know
how I feel about that.
Well, he's certainly a lot safer
up here, isn't he?
Of course, and I want him safe.
But I can't tell what he wants.
He won't talk to me.
He hardly even comes home.
He works all day, all night.
Barely eats,
barely speaks to me.
It's like something's
eating him away from inside.
He's just not the same.
He's not.
Facing death,
it changes a person.
It has to,
don't you think?
I guess you've noticed
a change in Walt.
Please.
What is this?
Your new lab.
[PEDER'S "TIMETAKES
THETIMETIMETAKES" PLAYING]
My God.
Thorium oxide
for a catalyst bed.
Look at the size
of this reaction vessel.
Oh, it's got...
It's gotta be 1200 liters.
Wow. Where--? Where--?
How did you know
how to put this all together?
I had excellent help,
as will you.
Quite a lot of planning
went into this.
I would say so.
The laundry upstairs,
I've owned it for years.
It receives large chemical
deliveries on a weekly basis,
detergents and such.
There is nothing
suspicious about it,
and my employees, to be sure,
are well-trained, trustworthy.
The filtration system
is state-of-the-art.
It will vent nothing
but clean, odorless steam,
just as the laundry does,
and through the very
same stacks.
I need 200 pounds per week
to make this
economically viable.
You would choose
your own hours, of course,
come and go as you please,
so long as the quota is met.
Sorry.
The answer is still no.
I have made a series
of very bad decisions,
and I cannot make
another one.
Why did you make
these decisions?
For the good of my family.
Then they weren't
bad decisions.
What does a man do,
Walter?
A man
provides for his family.
This cost me my family.
When you have children,
you always have family.
They will always be your
priority, your responsibility.
And a man...
A man provides.
And he does it
even when he's not appreciated
or respected
or even loved.
He simply bears up,
and he does it,
because he's a man.
[SHOWER RUNNING]
TED:
Any chance
we could grab a quick bite?
Thai place around the corner's
pretty good.
Um, I really gotta head home.
All right,
rain check, then.
WALT JR.:
She said it was the tofu.
[SKYLER LAUGHS]
Whatever. She's still
cute anyways.
Um...
Great dinner, Mom.
Can I be excused?
To do homework
or to play video games?
I can multitask.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah.
[BABY COOING]
[BABY CRYING]
You wanna take her?
[♪♪♪]
Yeah.
HANK:
Give me something, Andy.
Come on.
[AGENTS CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
Welded onto the back of a house.
Well, that's classy.
Christ.
Okay. Okay, thanks.
Hey, Janice. Janice.
That the last one?
Sorry, Hank.
That's all DMV had.
Twenty-nine early-'80s Bounders
registered in New Mexico.
Could you check again?
Now?
Can I do it after the party?
Janice, I'm...
I'm dead in the water here.
Okay, I'll check.
MAN:
Hey, how are you guys doing?
GOMEZ:
Oh, yeah, I'm gonna clean it
really good, I tell you.
All good.
Gomey.
GOMEZ: Yeah.
Time for the little bird
to fly the nest, huh?
The right guy for the job,
seeing as the bean-speak
comes natural and all.
Wanna know how to say
"get bent" in Spanish?
Just don't go native on me,
all right?
Oh, uh...
Hey, uh...
Here.
Know your enemy and all.
Fight the good fight,
brother.
I will.
Who got a drink
around here?
Your hunch was right.
One more RV.
DMV said the registration
wasn't renewed,
but then they realized
it was never filed
as non-operational
or destroyed.
No police report,
either.
[♪♪♪]
SKYLER:
I just don't know what the hell
I'm doing anymore, you know?
It's like I'm paralyzed,
like if I take a step
in any direction
I'm gonna make
a spectacular mistake.
God, I could go
for a glass of wine about now.
You wanna go to--?
Sorry, never mind.
Ech.
Anyway...
breaking news is
I am sleeping with my boss
and I don't know why.
Wow.
Yep.
That's a lie. I do know why.
I mean, he's a lovely guy.
He's a really good person,
but, I mean, it's not
like we're ever gonna...
[CHUCKLES]
Somehow, and I can't
actually believe it,
but my entire family
sees me as some sort of...
My own sister,
my brother-in-law.
My teenage son
tells me I'm a bitch.
And you say tell him
the truth.
Tell him about his father,
but I can't.
Ever.
How could I?
And this man
that I'm seeing, you know,
as wrong as I know it is,
as much as I know I'm probably
doing it to make Walt leave me,
it is the only thing in my day
where I don't feel...
like I'm...
drowning.
So he knows
about this other man?
Yeah.
So then he'll sign?
Um, Walt says he's not
going anywhere,
so that's a really brilliant
gambit on my part. Yep.
Genius.
He keeps money in the house.
Your husband, the drug dealer?
How much money?
I didn't count it.
It's heavy.
A bag,
where he keeps it.
Are you asking my permission
to spend this money?
No. God, no. I just--
No, I'm just, you know...
I'm just trying to just
talk it through. That's...
Let me just say
that I'm half as qualified
and twice the price
of a therapist.
There is nothing to
discuss here.
I'm just saying, you know?
We have a history.
He's the father
of my children,
and maybe
what he did, he--
He did it for the family.
Right?
Well, guess what.
That is one enormous load
of horse shit.
Okay.
I'm gonna spell this out
as simply as I can for you.
You are a fool to stay
in that house one minute longer.
If your husband won't leave,
then you go.
You are now an accessory
after the fact.
You are culpable.
You, your children, you could
lose everything you own.
Do you understand?
All courtesy of this criminal
you refuse to divorce.
I didn't marry a criminal.
Well,
you're married to one now.
SAUL:
How's about we run through this
one more time,
especially where I do the
talking, you don't say jack?
Oh, I'm gonna say jack.
I'm gonna say plenty.
What did we say about
escalating, huh?
Who's got your back here?
Me, all right?
I'm gonna take care of things.
What are the parameters
of this sobriety thing
you got going?
What do you mean?
Can you take a Xanax?
Because I got a drawer
full of them.
I get them
from my "chiropractor."
Vietnamese, 5-foot tall.
She adjusts you to "completion."
Her name's Kim Nu Suong,
as delicious as it sounds.
I should give you her card.
Hell with this.
I'm out of here.
WOMAN [OVER INTERCOM]:
He's here.
Send him in.
Hello, Walt.
Good to see you.
Please, have a seat here.
Mr. Pinkman, if you will.
You're late.
Gentlemen, if we could come
to some accommodation here now.
There's always a way
to oil everyone's lock.
This young man is prepared to
offer you a sweetheart of a deal
for doing
precisely nothing.
Really?
Ten percent of all future
profits from his solo venture.
That's money you get paid
for walking down to the mailbox.
Consider it a gesture of respect
for your valuable contribution
to the business thus far.
I'm sure you'll agree
that's fair.
That's charity,
is what that is.
I do all the work.
He sits around on his fat ass
judging people.
Eh, eh. Escalating. Stop.
So there's that, but then
there's one small detail.
Clearly a mistake was made on
the part of our mutual associate
when he paid you half
of Jesse's earnings.
He must not have realized
that you two had come to
a parting of the ways.
Take it.
It belongs to you.
You're damn right
it belongs to me.
I knew I could count on you boys
to play nice. That's--
That almost brings a tear
to my eye.
Enjoy it.
Spend it in good health.
That is the last money you'll
ever earn in this business.
What the hell is that
supposed to mean?
I hate to break it
to you, Jesse,
but our mutual associate
was only using you
to get to me.
What are you talking about?
See, he needs someone
with expertise,
someone who knows
what he's doing.
In other words,
he needs me.
You're telling me
you're cooking again?
Yeah. Let's see,
how should I put this?
I'm in.
You're out.
Whoa, whoa, Walt,
hold on there.
What was the offer,
if I may ask?
It's 3 million
for three months of my time.
SAUL:
You're gonna need that money
laundered. Of course.
What was our deal before?
Seventeen percent.
That's a shade high.
Let's settle on an even 15.
That's a nice round number.
Five percent.
Fourteen's fair.
Five.
Thirteen.
Twelve. For old times' sake.
Five.
I'm a reasonable guy.
It's a short-term deal.
Ten even, but I can't go any
lower and still respect myself.
Five.
What in the hell just happened?
You're my lawyer, not his.
That's the way of the world,
kid. Go with the winner.
You think this will stop me
from cooking?
Cook whatever you like.
As long as it's that ridiculous
Chili P or some other dreck,
but don't even think
about using my formula.
Just try and stop me, bitch.
[GRUNTING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
Yes?
Hi there, Mrs. Ortega?
Yes.
Hi, I'm Hank Schrader.
I'm with the
Drug Enforcement Administration.
We're interested in an RV
that's registered
to your name and address.
Do you have an RV?
I did.
It was stolen months ago.
Stolen, huh? Yeah.
Well, then I'm curious as to why
the theft was never reported.
I'm not seeing any records of
it with the police or the DMV.
I just
didn't get around to it.
May I ask why?
I mean, it's a great way
to get the family together
for an affordable vacation.
It must've been a blow
when it went missing.
It was.
Do you have any ideas at all
who might've taken it?
I didn't want him arrested.
He ran with a bad crowd,
but he was never a bad person.
I thought he could turn
his life around.
Who are we talking about,
Mrs. Ortega?
My son.
I'd really like
to speak with him.
He's passed away.
He was shot two months ago.
What was your son's name?
Christian.
Christian Ortega.
Was his nickname Combo?
[♪♪♪]
Thanks for this.
I really appreciate it.
[♪♪♪]