[♪♪♪]
[MARCO LAUGHING]
[BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH]
[PHONE RINGING]
Sí.
[IN SPANISH]
Why?
Why is this still
under discussion?
No. No, no, no.
I don't like him.
I don't care who he knows.
We're supposed to trust
him with our products.
Big man.
Big Generalissimo!
Big fry cook is more like it.
The "Chicken Man."
You will do what you want.
But you have my vote.
[MARCO SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHS]
Never trust
a South American.
Dirty, dirty people.
[MARCO LAUGHING]
[MARCO SPEAKING SPANISH
AND LAUGHS]
[IN SPANISH]
He broke my toy!
He was just having fun.
You'll get over it.
No! I hate him!
I wish he was dead!
Whoo-hoo. Ha, ha.
[WHISTLES]
Marco.
MARCO:
Sí.
Grab your old uncle
a beer, would you?
No, no. A cold one.
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
This is what you wanted.
Your brother dead. Right?
[LEONEL SHOUTING
IN SPANISH]
You're going to have to
try harder than that
if you want to save him.
How much longer do you think
he has down there?
One minute? Maybe more?
Maybe less?
[GASPS]
[LEONEL SPEAKS SPANISH]
[COUGHING]
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Family is all.
[COUGHING]
[♪♪♪]
Hey, you got nothing on me, yo.
All right, you can call
my lawyer, Saul Goodman.
Talk to my lawyer, all right?
You hear me?
I got nothing to say.
I told you, you can call my--
Christ!
You got my cell phone number,
you had my wife's name!
How did you do it?
Talk! Who you working with?
[♪♪♪]
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
Yes, sir.
If, uh,
you're ready to talk,
they wanna get a statement.
Your side of what happened here.
Or we can hold them off
till another time.
Maybe you wanna
talk to a lawyer.
There it is.
[CLICKS]
Heh. Yo, Adrian.
Rocky called, he wants
his face back. Heh, heh.
Come on, I gotta cheer you up.
You see that?
That's your
get-out-of-jail-free card.
You understand, right?
I mean, just blink once
if you're following. Heh, heh.
The DEA's worst nightmare
is that face out in public.
They'll have to steer a wide
berth of young Master Pinkman
for fear of the PR poop storm
that will rain down on them
if this story ever gets out.
I mean, this beating?
Best thing for you.
You're home free.
Good, right?
Right.
WALT:
Oh, my God.
You're now officially
the cute one of the group.
Paul, meet Ringo.
Ringo, Paul.
This is-- I, uh--
Jesse, I'm--
I am so sorry for this.
This should not have happened.
But it did.
No thanks to you.
But the plan did work.
We would've been
locked up right now
if we didn't lure him away.
But this--
This-- I just--
I never saw this coming.
So...
What, uh--?
What happens now?
JESSE:
I'll tell you what happens now.
Your scumbag brother-in-law
is finished.
Done.
You understand?
I will own him
when this is over.
Every cent he earns,
every cent his wife earns
is mine.
Anyplace he goes,
anywhere he turns,
I'm gonna be there,
grabbing my share.
He'll be scrubbing toilets
in Tijuana for pennies,
and I'll be standing over him
to get my cut.
He'll see me when he wakes
up in the morning
and when he crawls to sleep
in whatever rat hole
is left for him
after I shred his house down.
I will haunt his crusty ass
forever
until the day
he sticks a gun up his mouth
and pulls the trigger
just to get me out of his head.
That's what happens next.
SAUL:
Uh, my advice:
That's probably
not a good strategy.
I mean, they're scared
of you right now.
They want nothing
to do with you.
But if you hit them,
they're forced to hit back hard.
I mean, they will turn over
every rock hither,
thither and yon,
until someone spills
the beans on you
and anyone associated with you,
present company included.
Yes, I think what Saul is saying
makes a lot of sense.
Jesse, move on with your life.
Leave it behind, all of it.
Nothing changes
once I walk out of here.
I get myself a new RV
and go start cooking again.
How exactly do you think
you're going to get
away with that?
They will catch you.
So what?
What?
I have a get-out-of-jail-free
card.
Hey, I may have overstated
the power of your face.
Not this.
If the cops catch me,
I give them
what they want the most.
You.
They nab me,
I make a deal
to give up the great Heisenberg
and his million-dollar
drug ring.
You're my free pass,
bitch.
SAUL:
You're so sure.
Look, if he didn't give
up my name
while Hank was beating
him senseless,
he's never going to talk.
What do you think
that was in there, a bluff?
He wants
your brother-in-law.
There's gonna be
a parade of lawyers
creaming their Underoos
for a case like that.
I'd take it if it wouldn't cause
so much collateral damage.
And him cooking again?
Hey, when, not if,
he gets caught,
and he's facing 20 years,
what'll he do then?
Believe me, there's no honor
among thieves.
Except for us, of course.
Heh, heh.
No, he'll--
He'll come around.
And if he doesn't,
there may come a time
to talk options.
Options?
I'm convinced
Mr. Pinkman was involved
in the manufacture
and distribution
of phenyl-2 methamphetamine,
specifically what we call
the blue meth.
I tracked him to a scrap yard
where he stored
an early-'80s camper,
an RV.
While waiting for a warrant
to search this vehicle,
which I believe to be
a rolling meth lab,
I received a telephone call
telling me my wife Marie
had been injured in an accident.
Upon hearing the news,
I left Mr. Pinkman
and his vehicle
to tend to my wife.
Arriving at the hospital,
I learned the emergency call
was a hoax.
My wife, fortunately,
was unharmed.
[CLEARS THROAT]
So I immediately went back
to the salvage yard,
but the RV was gone.
Most likely destroyed on site.
And it was at this point
you drove to the home
of Jesse Pinkman?
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
I think we're done here.
Agent Schrader needs
to get home,
get some rest.
That's fine.
But just to confirm,
you're taking the Fifth here?
Yeah, that's correct.
MAN:
Okay. Well,
we just wanna give you
all a heads up.
Mr. Pinkman is pressing charges
in this matter.
He's given a detailed version
of events as he sees them.
The word of a meth head.
We know all about his history.
We're well aware,
but toxicology on Pinkman...
His blood is clean,
he's not using.
The kid is even refusing
his doctor-ordered pain meds,
far as we can tell.
So, um...
where do we go from here?
A couple of gentlemen
from OPR will come down,
probably tomorrow morning.
Janice will give us
an exact time on that.
And you men will be continuing
your investigation, so...
Thanks for your time.
Right. We just--
We need one more thing.
A photo of Agent Schrader's
hands. For the record.
Yes, of course.
Bandage off, if you would.
On the table is fine.
Flat on the table. That's fine.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
[CHATTING INDISTINCTLY]
[SOBBING]
MARIE:
It's all gonna work out.
You've been too good to them
for too many years.
HANK:
I hope it goes without saying
we're not talking to anybody
about this, okay?
MARIE:
Okay.
HANK:
Marie, who?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hi.
Do you have a minute?
Sure.
I guess crime does pay.
I don't suppose you just
came by to insult me.
No. We need to talk.
You heard about Hank?
About what happened
with this, um, Jesse Pinkman?
Yes, I know.
Whatever Hank
was investigating,
him trying to find an RV,
is there any danger
that could lead back to you?
No.
Why would it?
Is this why you're here?
I'm here to talk about Hank.
You know what's gonna
happen to him
if this Pinkman
presses charges?
Hank could lose everything.
I thought maybe, um,
there's a way
you could help him.
How?
Contact Pinkman.
Get him to drop the charges.
Look, Skyler, I don't know
what kind of relationship
you picture me having
with this person.
I'm not asking.
He was-- He's--
He's not my friend.
It's not as
if we were even close.
I'm-- I'm not asking.
But there must be something
you could say.
Isn't it even worth a try?
Hank is your family.
[WHISPERS]
Not currently.
What?
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I said, not currently.
I'm late. I have to go.
[MUSIC IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE
PLAYING ON STEREO]
GALE:
Hello.
[STEREO TURNS OFF]
I was starting to get worried.
Car trouble.
Oh, that's a bummer.
You should call me next time.
I'll pick you up.
Uh-huh.
No sandals today?
I just thought...
A bit more professional.
Well, everything is on track.
We got our distillate.
Just waiting to--
Let's get our trays ready.
Clean, no moisture.
Done.
Is our, uh--?
Our solvent filtered?
I thought you might ask that.
Done.
That's good.
Hand in glove,
that's what we strive for.
You know, this might
be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
[CHUCKLES]
So you the gentlemen?
Lucky you boys caught me,
I got a load to pick
up in Memphis.
I can hammer it out in about 15,
but there's this girl,
Lolly. Maybe Fran.
She's got this fetish,
she likes to get peed on.
I was hoping to see her tonight
but she wants
to sleep before 10,
so I wanna wrap it up here ASAP
because traffic can be a wild
card, rubber-necking and such.
Surprising thing is,
women who like to get peed on
tend to be from warmer climates.
You'd think the ones in colder
zones would be more inclined.
Maybe it's a shock
if the body's not acclimated,
but, you know, I leave that
for smarter minds than me.
Science is a mystery.
Well, take a gander.
Prices are negotiable.
Buying in bulk gets
you a discount.
I'm running a special
on these little honeys.
JHPs. Hollow-point bullets,
known by the natives
as Black Death. Check it out.
Like that? So sweet,
you wanna lick it.
Nickel-plated brass casing,
Lubalox coat.
Sucker has six razor claws
that expand upon impact:
[MAKES SWOOSH NOISE]
Shred your mama's head
like a cabbage.
Keep it. On the house.
I've been windjamming enough.
What you looking for,
what it is you need.
What can I do you for?
Vests.
Vests?
Hell, yeah, we got vests.
Right here.
Sleek, comfortable,
thermally bonded,
non-interwoven Kevlar fibre.
Stop a bullet like a soft wang
against a Quaker girl.
Ain't getting through.
And lightweight? So lightweight,
you'll forget you're wearing it.
They work?
Sure as shit, they do.
I don't leave home without it.
[GRUNTING]
What the hell?
You broke my freaking rib,
you maniac son of a bitch.
[GRUNTING]
You're welcome!
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
Gale.
What temperature
did you set here?
Here?
Station five, 75 C.
I said 85.
Eight-five.
I wrote it down.
You said 75.
I wrote it.
Well, you wrote it wrong.
That's not what I said.
I said 85.
It's always been 85.
Not 75. Not 95.
Eighty-five.
This is chemistry.
Degrees matter.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
Great.
You're sorry, meanwhile,
you've just brewed 50 gallons
of useless sludge.
Congratulations.
Just dump it. Dump it all.
This batch is ruined.
[MACHINE SHUTS DOWN]
You look nice.
I look like a TV weatherman.
You want a coffee?
No.
I squeezed some orange juice.
You want a glass
of orange juice?
I'm all right.
What are you
gonna tell them?
Here's what
you'll tell them.
He attacked you.
He attacked me?
He swung at you with something.
Swung at me?
He attacked you with a pipe.
A pipe.
It happened fast.
He resisted arrest
and muscle memory kicked in
and you had to disarm him.
Muscle memory.
Yes. Happens all the time.
Years of training, and your body
acted faster than your brain.
You had no choice
but to hit him.
You had to fight back.
Marie, Marie, Marie.
No.
I'm not gonna go
in there and lie.
It's some lowlife
degenerate versus you,
doing the job
you're supposed to.
Why should you
be the one who pays
for doing the right thing?
Oh, baby, it wasn't
the right thing.
It's not what the job is.
I'm supposed
to be better than that.
And you made one mistake.
No, it wasn't one mistake.
I've been--
[SIGHS]
I've been...
unraveling, you know?
I don't
sleep at night anymore.
I freeze.
I freeze up.
My chest gets all tight.
I can't breathe.
Just--
I panic.
Ever since that Salamanca thing.
I mean, Tuco Salamanca.
If ever a scumbag deserved
a bullet between the eyes...
It changed me.
And I can't seem to control it.
I tried to fight it.
But then...
El Paso.
And it's just gotten worse.
What I did to Pinkman,
that's not who I'm supposed
to be. That's not me.
All this,
everything that's happened, I--
I swear to God, Marie,
I think the universe
is trying
to tell me something,
and I'm finally...
ready to listen.
[EXHALES]
I'm just not the man
I thought I was.
I think I'm done as a cop.
WALT:
Now, this is not
an easy decision,
but it is one
that I have to make.
I'm sorry.
This whole Gale
situation, he's--
He's just not working out.
Yes, now.
It may sound unorthodox,
but I think
our first best option
is Jesse Pinkman.
Hello?
No, look. There's a shorthand
that exists between us,
experience together
at a level that, quite frankly,
I'm just never going
to reach with Gale.
Look, Mr. Fring,
when I accepted your offer,
I was told the lab is mine.
And I know best how to run it.
Thank you.
Yes, I will. I will.
Okay. Goodbye.
WALT:
Listen, something's come up.
I think it's a good opportunity.
There's been a job opening.
I need a new lab assistant.
I already did my time.
Why don't you just go get
yourself a monkey?
I don't want a monkey.
I want you.
Oh, gee, thanks.
Well, not interested.
I got my own thing going on.
And nice try, saving
your asshead brother-in-law.
That's not why I'm here, Jesse.
There's more.
It's more than an assistant.
Partners.
We'll be partners again.
Split everything fifty-fifty,
just like before.
One-point-five
million dollars each.
No.
I don't think you heard--
I heard you fine.
I said no.
Let me understand this.
You're turning down
one and a half million dollars--
I am not
turning down the money.
I am turning down you.
You get it?
I want nothing to do with you.
Ever since I met you,
everything
I've ever cared about
is gone.
Ruined, turned to shit,
dead, ever since I hooked up
with the great Heisenberg.
I have never been more alone.
I have nothing!
No one!
All right? It's all gone!
Get it?
No.
No, no. Why--?
Why would you get it?
What do you even care,
as long as you get
what you want?
Right?
You don't give a shit about me.
You said I was no good.
I'm nothing.
Why would you want me, huh?
You said my meth
is inferior, right?
Right? Hey, you said
my cook was garbage!
Hey, screw you, man!
Screw you.
[JESSE SOBBING]
Your meth is good, Jesse.
As good as mine.
[SIGHS]
[PHONE VIBRATING]
Yeah.
JESSE:
Fifty-fifty.
Yes, fifty-fifty.
Okay.
Partners.
Good.
And this is the statement
you want to give?
Yes, sir.
Hank, you don't have to do this.
No, I--
I do.
I'm good.
So we understand
if we write it up like that,
you'll sign it.
That's the way it happened.
I accept the consequences.
In the light of these facts,
as of this moment,
you're suspended without pay.
I have to ask you to hand over
your badge and your gun.
Yes, sir.
Schrader.
Hold up.
Yes, sir?
I just wanted
to tell you something.
And to be clear,
you didn't hear it from me.
Don't get your hopes up,
but the word in the pipeline is
Pinkman isn't pressing charges.
Why not?
Who the hell knows?
Maybe you have a guardian angel.
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
HANK:
It went fine.
Well, fine
means what it means, yeah.
I'll, uh--
I'll tell you all about it
when I get home, okay?
Yeah. It's--
Yeah, it's just--
I don't know, baby,
I just think--
I think we may be okay. Yeah.
Okay. I love you too.
[PHONE RINGING]
Schrader.
MAN:
I need you to listen
very carefully.
Two men are coming to kill you.
Come again?
They're approaching your car.
You have one minute.
I don't get the gag,
jagoff. Who is this?
They're coming.
Hello?
[PHONE HANGS UP]
[DIALING]
Hey, li--
Gomey, this is Hank, I don't
know what that call was,
but it's dumb even
by your standards,
so call me when you get this.
[♪♪♪]
[CAR DOOR LOCK CHIRPS]
[HORN HONKS]
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOTS]
Argh!
[CAR ALARM HONKING]
[GRUNTS]
[IN SPANISH]
Finish him.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Jesus.
[SCREAMING]
[GUN CLICKS]
[IN ENGLISH]
No.
[IN SPANISH]
Too easy.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
[GUN COCKS]
[CAR ALARM
CONTINUES HONKING]
[♪♪♪]