MAN:
In the little village
where I was born,
life moved at a slower pace,
yet felt all the richer for it.
There, my two uncles were known
far and wide
for their delicious cooking.
They seasoned
their zesty chicken
using only the freshest
herbs and spices.
People called them
Los Pollos Hermanos,
"The Chicken Brothers."
Today, we carry
on their tradition
in a manner that would make
my uncles proud.
The finest ingredients
are brought together
with loving care,
then slow-cooked to perfection.
Yes, the old ways
are still best
at Los Pollos Hermanos.
But don't take my word for it.
One taste and you'll know.
[♪♪♪]
[WHIRRING]
JESSE:
Two-oh-one-point-six.
Jesus, seriously.
Better over than under.
Over by a pound and a half.
I thought you were all,
like, precise.
Whatever. We'll just
save it out till next week.
We ship it as is.
What,
are we running a charity?
Come on, man.
We're gonna take it out.
Leave it.
One batch, one ship.
Stop complicating things.
Why are you purposely
giving him free meth?
These bitches are bleeding
us enough already.
You are paid
extraordinarily well.
Why can't you just
appreciate that?
Yeah. Hey, I been
crunching numbers.
You've been crunching numbers?
Yeah.
And I don't gotta be
a mathematician to figure out
that this deal you made
is bullshit.
We both earn--
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I know.
A million and a half each.
Whoop-dee-doo.
What's he getting, huh?
Say he's wholesaling
at 40 large a pound.
That's probably high.
High. What, for our stuff?
That's what I was getting.
All right, look,
say he's getting 40 a pound.
All right, 200 pounds a week
for three months.
And, like, what happens
at the end of the three months?
Look, whatever.
Two hundred pounds a week
for three months.
That's 2400 pounds.
Twenty-four hundred
times 40,000 is--
And I swear to God,
I double-checked this
like 10 times.
Ninety-six million dollars.
All right? Ninety-six million.
Ninety-six to our three.
That is messed up, yo.
That is so messed up.
Fairness-wise,
I can't even--
Jesse.
You are now a millionaire
and you're complaining?
What world do you live in?
One where the dudes who are
actually doing all the work
ain't getting fisted.
What is going
on with you lately?
What's happened to you?
Hang on, can't we just--?
Hey,
we gotta hash this out.
Hey, what's more important
than money?
[DOOR SLAMS]
[WHISPERING]
These things they
laughingly call pillows,
I would not give them
to prison inmates.
You want me
to go ask for another?
No, just remind me
to bring his from home.
They're not
moving his legs enough.
[KNOCKING]
GOMEZ: Hey, everybody.
Hi, Marie.
Is it okay if I visit?
Yeah.
His color looks good.
[FAINTLY]
Gomey, is that you?
Buddy, yeah, it's me.
That's you, Gomey?
Yeah, Hank.
I'm right here.
Come here. Closer.
What is it?
Closer.
Asshole.
[LAUGHS]
Man, he got you good.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm glad to see you still have
your twisted sense of humor.
[LAUGHS, THEN COUGHS]
God.
Hey, check this out.
I got something
that'll make you feel better.
Been keeping an eye
on that blue meth of yours.
Six, seven weeks, nothing.
Then all of a sudden, boom,
it's popping up everywhere.
Look at the new locations.
Texas, Nevada, up in Farmington.
Even right here in town.
A teener here and there,
you know,
strictly street-level amounts.
Man, it's crazy.
How exactly is that supposed
to make me feel better?
Because you were right.
You're the only one that
saw this coming.
HANK:
Well, three cheers for me.
[CLICKING]
[GROANING]
This thing doesn't do
a damn thing.
Hank, it's probably
still on lock-out.
It's been an hour, right?
I'm hurting here.
I could use some meds.
I'll go find somebody.
[GRUNTS]
Hey, no more shop talk.
Sorry.
I didn't see it coming.
GOMEZ:
What? Damn right, you did.
No, I didn't see shit.
Day late and dollar short,
as usual.
The only reason
I'm even breathing
is I got a warning call.
SKYLER:
A warning call?
What do you mean?
One minute
before they attacked me,
somebody called my cell
and told me to expect it.
A voice scrambler.
Could have been anybody.
Marie's got my phone somewhere,
if you want to run the incoming.
Not that you're gonna learn
anything worth knowing.
GOMEZ:
I don't get it. Cartel hit?
Who would have
called to warn you?
HANK:
I don't know.
[GRUNTS]
Oh, Jesus.
Come on already.
Okay.
[♪♪♪]
[SOFTLY]
Damn.
[GOMEZ SIGHS]
Skyler, I had nothing to do--
Are we safe?
Yes.
Are you safe?
Absolutely.
GROUP LEADER:
Jesse?
What about you?
Face looks better.
How's it all going?
Anything you wanna
tell us about?
What,
like my interesting life?
Uh, one day pretty much
bleeds into the next.
Been working a lot.
Got a job.
GROUP LEADER: Job is good.
It's, um, it's in a Laundromat.
It's totally corporate.
Corporate Laundromat.
JESSE:
It's, like, rigid.
All kinds of red tape.
My boss is a dick.
The owner, super dick.
I'm not worthy to meet him,
but I guess everybody's
scared of the dude.
The place is full
of dead-eyed douche bags,
the hours suck and nobody knows
what's going on, so...
Sounds kind of Kafkaesque.
Yeah.
Totally Kafkaesque.
Majorly.
Ooh. From the U.S. attorney
in Santa Fe.
Very nice.
[CHUCKLES]
SKYLER:
You've got all these nice tulips
and baby's breath.
MARIE:
Oh, and this is chrysanthemum.
That looks like chrysanthemum.
SKYLER: Yeah.
MARIE: Look at these.
Aren't they beautiful?
Beautiful.
Wow, look at the size
of this basket.
It's got so many goodies in it.
Look, chocolate-covered pretzels
and cheese sticks
and some fancy designer olives.
You had me at cheese sticks.
Mm, you're gonna have to
fight me for those, Hank.
"Get well and best wishes
from Ted Beneke
and all the folks
at Beneke Fabricators."
Wow, he gives you all
this time off and now this.
Get me a job there.
I know. He's great.
Boss hall of fame. I don't see
anything here from Kleinman.
They're gonna have
to get on the stick.
[KNOCKING]
How's everybody doing today?
MARIE:
Good. We're good.
How are you?
I'm very good.
Hi, Hank. Just gonna do a quick
peripheral response, all right?
See where we're at.
Moment of truth?
Yeah,
I wouldn't call it that.
All right, let's just
take a look here.
All right.
All right, now I want you
to tell me if you can feel this.
All right.
How about this?
Okay.
How about now?
Do that one again, would you?
Right there?
Yeah, yeah, I feel a tingle.
On a scale of one to ten,
ten being your normal
level of feeling
and one being no feeling at all.
Oh, I don't know.
Four?
Okay, four. Okay.
And how about there?
Yeah. Um, a six.
Okay, good.
And, um, here.
Yeah, still there.
A little less.
A three.
Okay.
All right, good.
Thank you very much,
Hank. Did good.
S-So this is good news,
right?
Oh, yeah,
definitely.
Gosh.
It looks like some nerve
function is returning.
Oh, thank God.
All right, so when do we get
him walking again?
DOCTOR:
Marie, it's important
that we manage our expectations.
We're talking about months
of very hard work.
And even then, the odds,
they're not great.
But you can't know
for sure.
No.
When does he start
physical therapy?
We've sent the paperwork
to your insurance.
It's high-priority.
We should have pre-authorization
in the next few days.
Certainly by early next week.
MARIE:
Next week?
No, that's not gonna do it.
I've looked into this.
And the sooner physical
therapy begins,
the better his chances are.
He needs daily sessions.
Isn't that right?
Well--
Actually,
your plan's treatment program
covers four sessions a week.
Actually,
she asked the doctor.
Um, plan-wise, four treatments
a week is fairly typical.
And the therapists in
your network are mostly fine.
Mostly fine. Okay, well,
there's a ringing endorsement.
Look, if Hank had
more physical therapy
with better therapists,
wouldn't it be more
likely he would walk?
It's very hard to say,
Marie.
Is the health plan's way
medically justifiable? Sure.
Is it absolutely optimal?
You know, screw it.
I'm gonna make sure
he gets what he needs.
They can reimburse me.
Mrs. Schrader, I get
your frustration. Really, I do.
But my best advice
is stay in the network.
Don't go out of pocket.
Physical therapy
is just the beginning.
We're talking nursing care,
modifications to your home,
occupational therapy,
medical equipment.
It could run into the hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
So what?
We're just supposed
to compromise on his care?
Well, if you don't follow
the insurance company's
procedures,
they may never pay you back.
I've seen patients
and their families go bankrupt
waiting to be reimbursed.
Who is the best physical
therapist that you know?
I can give you some names.
But they're not likely
to be on your plan.
MARIE:
To hell with the plan.
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[BELL RINGS]
Eh, there he is.
Finally. I went ahead
and started without you.
Ladies, this is Jesse-san.
He's in for the full treatment.
Hey, kick off your shoes.
Lay back.
Exfoliate.
Maybe later.
Where's the maestro,
out parking the minivan?
Do I look like his shadow?
Who cares where he's at?
What am I doing here?
Well, I was gonna have
you two flip a coin.
But since the genius
can't be bothered,
today's your lucky day.
Look around, kiddo.
It's all yours.
What?
This?
Yeah.
You are now the owner
of this fine establishment.
For free?
Free?
Oh, ladies, cover your ears.
No, not free.
Look, hey,
this is a squeaky-clean,
highly profitable--
At least potentially.
--local institution
looked upon with favor
by the Chamber of Commerce,
Better Business Bureau.
At $312,000, it's a steal.
Three hundred
and twelve thousand?
Don't you get it?
On the outside,
it's a nail salon, right?
On the inside,
it's the best money laundry
a growing boy could ask for.
Wait, wait, wait. Hey.
Ladies, thank you.
Good job. Come back here.
Sit. Come on, come on.
Humor me here for a second.
Now, you know you need
to launder your money, right?
Do you understand
the basics of it,
placement, layering,
integration?
I ain't buying no damn nail
salon, so just forget it.
Don't you want
to stay out of jail?
I mean, you wanna keep
your money and your freedom.
Because I got three little
letters for you: IRS.
If they can get Capone,
they can get you.
Hey, look. Here's you, right?
Pink, Pinkman. Get it?
Okay, here's your cash.
You're out on the town.
Yeah, you're partying hearty.
You're knocking boots
with the chicky babes.
Oh, who's this?
It's the tax man.
And he's looking at you.
Now, what does he see?
He sees a young fellow
with a big fancy house,
unlimited cash supply
and no job.
Now, what is the conclusion
the tax man makes?
I'm a drug dealer.
Enhh. Wrong.
Million times worse.
You're a tax cheat.
What do they do?
They take every penny,
and you go in the can
for felony tax evasion.
Ouch! What was your mistake?
You didn't launder
your money.
Now, you give me
your money, okay?
That's called placement.
Hand me that little thing--
Bin.
This is the nail salon, right?
I take your dirty money
and I slip it into the salon's
nice clean cash flow.
That's called layering.
Final step, integration.
The revenues from the salon
go to the owner. That's you.
Your filthy drug money
has been transformed
into nice, clean,
taxable income,
brought to you
by a savvy investment
in a thriving business.
So you want me to buy this place
so I can pay taxes.
I'm a criminal, yo.
Yeah, and if you wanna
stay a criminal
and not become,
say, a convict,
maybe you should grow up
and listen to your lawyer.
Right, so you can
get your 5 percent.
No, that's 17 percent.
I heard you say 5. You said
it right in front of me.
Yeah, that was for your partner.
It's privileges
of seniority and all.
But for you,
it's the usual,
17 percent
and that's a bargain.
Hey, what?
You-- Hey, listen--
Come on, I'm talking to you
about your future here.
Listen to reason.
GUS:
How is your brother-in-law?
He'll live.
Good. I'm glad.
Walter, you seem troubled.
How can I help you?
I asked to see you
in order to
clear the air.
There are some issues
that could cause
a misunderstanding between us,
and I think it's
in our best interests
to just lay the cards
on the table.
That's the best way
to do business.
My brother-in-law,
moments before he was attacked,
someone called to warn him.
I believe that same person
was protecting me.
Those two men, the assassins,
I believe I was
their prime target.
But that somehow,
they were steered away from me
to my brother-in-law.
Because of this intervention,
I am alive.
And yet I think that this person
was playing a much deeper game.
He made that phone call
because he wanted a shootout,
not a silent assassination.
In one stroke,
he bloodied both sides,
set the American
and Mexican governments
against the cartel
and cut off the supply
of methamphetamine
to the Southwest.
If this man had
his own source of product
on this side of the border,
he would have
the market to himself.
The rewards would be enormous.
We're both adults.
I can't pretend I don't know
that person is you.
I want there to be
no confusion.
I know I owe you my life.
And more than that,
I respect the strategy.
In your position,
I would have done the same.
One issue which troubles me...
I don't know what happens
when our three-month
contract ends.
What would you like
to happen?
You know why I do this.
I want security for my family.
Then you have it.
Three million for three months.
That was our agreement.
Extended annually,
12 million a year.
Call it 15. Open-ended.
Would that be agreeable?
Hm.
[♪♪♪]
[HORN HONKING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
GROUP LEADER:
Part of the reason we talk about
what gets us riled
up in our daily lives
is to help each other
put a finger
on what our relapse
triggers might be,
head off our disease
before it comes back.
So, anyone?
Free license to bitch and moan.
How often do you get that?
Jesse, last time,
you seemed down
about your job
at the Laundromat.
Let me ask something.
If you had the chance
to do anything you wanted,
what would you do?
Make more green, man.
A lot more.
Forget about money.
Assume you have all you want.
JESSE:
Um...
I don't know.
I guess I would make something.
GROUP LEADER:
Like what?
I don't know if it even matters,
but, uh...
work with my hands, I guess.
Building things, like carpentry
or bricklaying or something?
I took this vo-tech class
in high school, woodworking.
I took a lot of vo-tech classes,
because it was just
a big jerk-off.
But this one time,
I had this teacher
by the name of, uh,
Mr., uh, Mr. Pike.
I guess he was like a Marine
or something before he got old.
He was hard of hearing.
My, uh--
My project for his class
was to make this wooden box.
You know, like a small, um--
Just like a-- Like a box,
you know, to put stuff in.
So I wanted to get the thing
done as fast as possible.
I figured I could cut classes
for the rest of the semester
and he couldn't flunk me
as long as I, you know,
made the thing.
So I finished it
in a couple days.
And it looked pretty lame,
but it worked,
you know, for putting stuff
in or whatnot.
So when I showed
it to Mr. Pike
for my grade,
he looked at it and said:
"Is that the best you can do?"
At first I thought to myself,
"Hell yeah, bitch.
"Now give me a D and shut up
so I can go blaze
one with my boys."
[PEOPLE CHUCKLING]
I don't know. Maybe it was
the way he said it, but...
It was like he wasn't exactly
saying it sucked.
He was just asking me honestly,
"Is--
Is that all you got?"
And for some reason,
I thought to myself:
"Yeah, man, I--
I can do better,"
so I started from scratch.
I made another, then another.
And by the end of the semester,
by like box number five,
I had built this thing.
You should have seen it.
It was insane.
I mean, I built it
out of Peruvian walnut
with inlaid zebrawood.
It was fitted with pegs,
no screws.
I sanded it for days
until it was smooth as glass.
Then I rubbed
all the wood with tung oil
so it was rich and dark.
It even smelled good.
You know, you put nose
in it and breathed in, it was--
[CHUCKLES]
It was perfect.
What happened to the box?
I, um,
I gave it to my mom.
GROUP LEADER:
Nice.
You know what I'm gonna say,
don't you?
It's never too late.
They have art co-ops
that offer classes,
adult extension program
at the university.
You know, I didn't give
the box to my mom.
I traded it
for an ounce of weed.
He's a hero. You don't deny
coverage to a hero.
They'll say they're
not denying coverage.
No, no, I'm agreeing with you.
But I went through
all this with Walt.
You'll burn through
your savings, and then what?
Well, you two managed,
right?
You said yourself
that Elliot and Gretchen's money
didn't cover everything.
Jesus, I gotta get back.
What? No.
No, no, no, you should rest.
Look, why don't you go
in and take a long bath?
I put some fresh
sheets on the bed.
I wanna be there
in case he wakes up.
With all they're giving him,
he'll sleep till morning.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
TED: Hey, Sky.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Thought I'd stop by
to see how you're holding up.
Is this a bad time?
Hi.
Uh, Marie, this is Ted,
my boss.
Oh, you're Ted.
I've heard so much about you.
Thank you for your gift basket.
That was really thoughtful.
It was nice. Thank you.
Cheese sticks.
You're welcome.
We care about Skyler so much,
that naturally that extends
to the whole family.
Are you coming in?
Oh, yeah, you should.
I'm sorry. Come on in, Ted.
Thanks. Okay.
We were having some wine.
Would you like a glass?
No, no, thanks.
I'm just on my way home.
I just thought I'd--
You know,
I am really beat.
I think I'm gonna
take that bath.
Okay.
It was nice to meet you, Ted,
and thank you again.
Nice to meet you too, Marie.
Give my best wishes
to your husband.
I will.
Thanks for stopping by,
but it's actually not the best
time for a visit, so...
Can we just talk for a minute?
I know you need to be
with your family,
but I haven't heard
from you in days
and I left messages--
I'm so sorry.
You gave me all that time off
and I really should've--
That's not my point.
I care about you. That's all.
Ted, I-- It's just
this whole thing with Hank
has been one nonstop horror
show, you know, so...
Well, I just want you to know
that I'm here for you.
Thank you.
Um, but I really do
need you to...
Okay.
Okay?
Skyler, I gotta say,
your sister seeing me here,
I mean, so what?
I'm divorced.
You're divorced. So what?
Okay, let's talk about
it later, Ted, okay?
Is there some reason
for secrecy?
Later. Not now.
Skyler, just tell me--
You really wanna do this now?
Are you gonna make
me do this right now?
Well...
Yeah, you're right.
Bad idea to come here.
Ted, I'm--
I'll see you in a day or two.
Back at the office.
Take as much time
as you want.
BADGER:
I can't believe
you had to crush the RV.
Must've been depressing.
PETE:
For real. That's a stone loss.
JESSE:
No one misses it more than me.
Free to cook anytime, anywhere.
No quotas, no one to answer to.
What's the point
of being an outlaw
when you got
responsibilities?
Darth Vader had
responsibilities.
He was responsible
for the Death Star.
True that.
Two of them bitches.
Just saying.
Devil's advocate.
I gotta pay taxes?
What's up with that?
That's messed up.
That's Kafkaesque.
Church.
Right.
Let's kick it back
into gear. All right?
Let's start slinging again.
Boo-yah!
Shh.
Let's do it.
Life's too short, I say.
Hells yeah, bitches.
We don't need no RV.
All we need is a bicycle,
some Drano, soda bottles.
No, no. No shake-and-bake.
Where's your
self-respect? Come on.
Ain't top-shelf, but we could
at least move it.
Still kind of dry out there.
It'll sell on the street.
And who says we sell
on the street?
Maybe I know a whole new market.
Maybe all we need is the meth.
[BREATHES]
[SCALE BEEPS]
[ROD TAYLOR'S "MR. MONEY MAN"
PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES]
What's the yield?
Hey.
The yield. Come on.
Uh, two-oh-one-
point-eight.
GROUP LEADER:
I see a couple new faces.
Anybody wanna introduce
themselves?
Don't all speak at once.
Yeah.
So my name's Brandon.
Okay, Brandon. You wanna tell us
something about yourself?
Well, why I'm here,
it's just one thing.
It's meth.
It's bad.
Thought I had it kicked
a couple times, you know.
But then, Jesus,
this new version of it
hit the streets,
and, wow.
Not that blue stuff.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't raise my hand.
No, go ahead.
This is what we do.
Yeah, exactly, the blue stuff.
You had it too?
Yeah, bro.
I wish I never even heard of it.
It was like lighting
my whole head on fire.
BADGER:
Yeah. That stuff
will burn you down.
Only reason I have
a hope in hell
is because it's long gone.
That's the shame of it.
BADGER:
No, no, man. Don't tell me that.
PETE:
I hear it's back in town.
Stay strong, brother.
Stay strong.
WOMAN:
It's gonna be okay.
MARIE:
I swear to God, I'll do it.
I will go to the press.
I'll go to 48 Hours.
I'll go to Nightline.
I don't know if there's
Nightline anymore.
Doesn't matter.
They will all take it
and they will run with it,
because he is a hero
and he is not going to be
in a wheelchair at 43.
Jesus.
Listen, Marie.
I know Skyler's
already told you this,
but if there's ever
anything that you need,
anything at all...
It's good to have you here.
Both of you.
I just wish there was
something more that we could do.
Walt.
We can always pay their bills.
MARIE:
Please, it's tens of thousands
of dollars.
We have the money,
more than enough.
Walt earned it.
Skyler.
SKYLER: I think Marie
should know the truth.
Skyler, I really don't think
this is a good idea.
I think that--
He earned it gambling.
Walt and I, uh...
we've had our problems lately.
You know that.
And, uh, what it all
came down to really
was money.
Pure and simple.
When Walt was diagnosed, it,
um...
it changed him.
And looking back, I don't think
I ever really understood
what it was
that he was going through.
It was more
than facing death.
It was knowing that he was gonna
leave behind...
...nothing.
And so that's how
this all started.
For better or worse,
he wanted to provide.
And so he paid his medical bills
the only way he knew how.
I thought that Elliot
and Gretchen
paid for your treatment.
Yeah, I thought so too.
The truth is he never took
their money. Not a dime.
He was too proud to take what
he considered to be charity.
Isn't that right?
So he put his mind
to it and...
Well, you know how Walt is.
He's a problem-solver.
And he read books and he did
a whole bunch of research,
and he came up
with this system.
A system?
A system for counting cards
in blackjack.
W-What do you mean,
like Rain Man?
Well, I don't pretend
to understand,
you know, all the details,
but he was convinced
that if he put enough money
into it, he'd have a--
God, what is it?
A statistical edge?
Yes, statistical--
So--
Um, yeah.
So he,
every spare minute,
Walt was at some
card table somewhere.
And at first he went
to the casinos,
but then he realized that--
[WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OUTSIDE]
But then he realized
that the casinos report
your winnings to the IRS.
And if it gets reported,
your family might find out.
If you do not want
your family to find out,
you find another
place to gamble.
Like an illegal backroom game.
You remember all those long
walks that Walt used to take,
all that time he used
to spend away from home?
I guess for a couple
months there,
you were sort of leading
a double life, weren't you?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, y-your--
Your fugue state.
Was that some sort of cover?
No, no.
He did not
fake that, Marie.
The night
that Walt disappeared...
he lost $14,000.
[SIGHS]
It was his pension fund,
our savings,
basically every last dime
we had to our name, gone.
He couldn't live with it.
He was suicidal.
But you have to understand
that as soon as he got
out of the hospital,
he went right back
to gambling.
I mean, that's how deep
this went.
How could you
do that to her, Walt?
Anyway,
this system of his?
He finally got it to work.
So all this is to say
we have the money.
No more gambling.
But we have the money.
How much money?
Walt?
Uh...
Well...
it's into seven figures.
Oh.
MARIE:
Holy Mary, mother of God.
What can I say?
I did very well.
Marie,
you will take our money.
Use it to take care of Hank.
Please.
Marie, let us help.
Does Walt, Jr. know about this?
Absolutely not.
And I need to keep it that way.
And Hank, okay? Hank's got
enough on his mind right now.
Can we please keep
this between us?
Yeah. Yeah, I--
Yeah, I just--
I need to--
Yeah, okay. We'll talk
about it later.
How did you
come up with that?
I mean, where did
you possibly--?
I learned from the best.
Somehow,
something tells me that Hank
is here because of you.
And I'm not forgetting that.
[FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING]
[♪♪♪]