SKYLER:
♪ Hush, little baby
Don't say a word ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy
You a mockingbird ♪
♪ And if that mockingbird
Won't sing ♪
[BABY COOING]
♪ Mama's gonna buy you
A diamond ring ♪
♪ And if that diamond ring
Turns brass ♪
♪ Mama's gonna buy you
A looking glass ♪
♪ So hush, little baby
Don't you cry ♪
♪ Daddy loves you
And so do I ♪
[♪♪♪]
[ALARM BEEPING]
[BEEPING STOPS]
[♪♪♪]
Surprised he doesn't
make us do that.
JESSE:
The pack totally
has a pecking order.
And the head hyena,
he's the man, you know.
All the other ones have to,
like, kiss his ass.
I mean, literally.
It's so gross.
They have to lick his junk.
I can't believe they
even showed it on TV.
[GROANS]
Yo, if this is supposed
to be all, like,
major-league and all,
we should have equipment
maintainer guys.
And water boys, you know?
Yo, Gatorade me, bitch.
Get us a couple
flunkies in here.
Treat us right.
JESSE:
Okay, 15 hours starts now.
I'm gonna hit it,
if that's cool with you.
I don't understand.
What?
These numbers,
they just don't add up.
Told you.
Dude's totally boning us.
No, it's not that.
It's our output. We're off.
We're .14 percent off.
Point one-four.
That's, what, like--?
What does that mean?
It means we should be netting
more than we're netting.
So how far off are we?
It's not negligible.
Ball-parking at it,
I'd say we're a quarter
to a half a pound shy.
That's weird.
Well, what about spillage?
Spillage?
You know, when, like,
just stuff gets spilled.
Nothing gets spilled.
A little maybe.
What about evaporation?
It wouldn't account
for this much.
The materials aren't
out that long.
What about
the other one?
The drops, like on--
Like on, like, cold beer.
Condensation?
Yeah.
No.
Well, what about the crap
that gets left behind?
You know, all the gunk
we scrape out of the vats.
Gotta add up
to like a gallon each.
Did you work that in?
Vestiges.
Yeah. Vestiges.
Bet that's it.
Bet that's
totally it.
[CLAPS]
Hey, Mr. White.
Mr. White.
Huh?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, why?
Nothing.
Are you coming?
Yeah, in a minute.
All right, see you tomorrow.
[FLY BUZZING]
All right.
Shit.
Bastard.
Son of a--
[YELLS]
Come on, you--
Come on, come on.
Son of a--
Ah!
Come on.
Son of a bitch.
Ha!
That's great.
[GROANS]
All right.
[FLY BUZZING]
You little bastard.
Ooh! Ooh!
[COUGHING]
[FLY BUZZING]
[♪♪♪]
[WIND WHISTLING]
WALT:
Shut the door!
My ears are popping.
Shut the door. Move.
JESSE:
Feels like on an airplane.
What the hell's doing that?
WALT:
Positive pressure.
Positive what?
God, it frigging kills, yo.
Well, just move
your jaw around.
I am moving it around.
It's not working.
Just yawn or something.
Stop acting like
such a baby.
Damn.
What positive?
Positive what?
Pressure. I've turned
the ventilation up
to keep the outside out.
There's been
a contamination.
Wait. What?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, hold up.
WALT:
Something got into the lab.
So, uh, what do we do?
I mean, do we--?
Wait. Wait.
I mean,
shouldn't we be
wearing masks?
No, no, it's not that
kind of contaminant.
So it's, like,
not dangerous?
Mr. White,
talk to me here.
Not to us
particularly, no.
What the hell
is that?
This is, uh--
I made it.
So exactly what kind
of contaminant
are we dealing
with here?
A fly.
What do you mean?
A fly, like--
Like, what do you mean?
I mean, a fly.
A housefly.
Like, uh, one fly?
Singular?
What did it do?
It got into the lab.
I'm trying to get it out.
Okay? Understand?
No, man, not really.
I can't say that I'm really
following you here.
Dude, you scared
the shit out of me!
When you say it's
contamination, I mean,
I'm thinking like an Ebola
leak or something.
Ebola.
Yeah, it's a disease
on The Discovery Channel
where all your intestines
sort of just slip out
of your butt.
Thank you.
I know what Ebola is.
Uh-huh.
Now, tell me.
What would a
West African virus
be doing in our lab?
Hm?
So you're chasing
around a fly,
and in your world,
I'm the idiot.
Jesse, listen.
This fly--
No, any fly cannot be
in our lab.
It's a problem.
It's a contamination.
And that is in no way
a misuse of the word. Okay?
So in terms of keeping
our cook clean
and our product
unadulterated,
we need to take this
very seriously.
Now do you understand?
So is that
your fly-saber?
This is a swatter.
And it happens to work
quite well, thank you.
Uh-huh. Hey,
what happened
to your head?
Nothing. I'm fine.
You didn't hit it,
like really, really hard?
My head is not
the problem, Jesse.
The fly is the problem.
You didn't happen to maybe
try our product, did you?
Jesse, I know this seems
unusual to you, a layman.
A fly. I get it.
It seems insignificant, right?
But trust me,
in a highly controlled
environment such as this...
any pollutant...
no matter how small...
could completely...
Hello?
What?
Were you here all night?
Have you even slept?
No. Jesse, look.
I'm fine, okay?
Will you just please
focus on--?
[BEEPING]
[BEEPING STOPS]
Okay, look,
we're running late,
so let's just get started.
The sooner we do it,
the sooner we're done.
Fricking finally.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What are you doing?
It's time to alkaline.
Have you not heard
a word I said?
No cooking until this fly
is dealt with.
Have I been
speaking to myself?
The timer went off, yo.
How long is this batch
gonna be good for?
An hour? Two?
The batch will be
good for nothing
if we don't clear
the contaminant.
"Clear the
contaminant."
We're making meth here,
all right? Not space shuttles.
We're making nothing
until we catch this fly.
What fly? All right?
Where the hell is this fly?
Not like I even seen the thing.
Maybe your
positive pressure
blew it out the door
or something.
No, no, it is here.
It is around, okay?
He's around,
and I am not going
to expose this batch
to the open air
and contamination, period.
Now, you can leave me
to deal with this myself
or you can help me.
But you are right.
We are running
out of time.
So I need your answer
right now.
Okay.
Hey, tick-tock, yo.
Look, I like making
cherry product,
but let's keep it real,
all right?
We make poison for
people who don't care.
We probably have
the most
un-picky customers
in the world.
No, no, no.
No rationalizing.
We'll find it any minute.
Don't give up.
Did you know that there's
an acceptable level of rat turds
that can go into candy bars?
That's the government,
Jack.
Even the government
doesn't care that
much about quality.
You know what is okay
to put in hotdogs, huh?
Pig lips and assholes.
But I say, hey,
have at it, bitches,
because I love hotdogs.
And, you know,
see what I'm try--?
What are you doing?
Oh, hey.
Look, let me just top it off,
all right, really quick.
You know,
a little sodium hydroxide,
shut the lid. No harm done.
Then we're golden.
It stays closed.
That's an order.
You can't order shit,
Adolf, all right?
We're 50-50
partners, remember?
Ow!
God, what is your problem?
Freaking psycho. Oh!
Jesse.
Oh, God.
It, like, hit bone.
Jesse.
You see it, right?
You see it?
Yeah.
Get it.
You want me to get it?
Yes.
Whoa.
Slow. Move slowly.
I know. I'm moving
slowly, yeah.
Absolutely. I'm just gonna
need your swatter thing.
Come on.
Oh, yeah. It's okay,
come on.
Yeah.
Yeah, come on.
Just make it count.
Yeah, no, no,
I'm gonna--
I'm gonna make it count,
all right.
Okay. Now, on three.
Okay.
One--
Oh! Motherfuck--!
Yeah. You like that, huh?
Hurts, huh?
Did you get it?
I think so, yeah.
Where is it?
I don't know.
What does it matter?
Who cares? I got it.
Oh, Jesus, seriously?
Where is it?
It's right there. Look.
Look. See?
I told you I got it.
This is a raisin.
Look, I definitely got it,
man, all ri--
[FLY BUZZING]
Oh, man.
He's got some skills, yo.
I'll give him that.
Look.
I feel like I'm running out of
ways to explain this to you,
but once more,
I shall try.
This fly is a major
problem for us.
It will ruin our batch.
And we need to destroy it
and every trace
of it so we can cook.
Failing that...
we're dead.
There is no more room
for error.
Not with these people.
All right, how about we
go get some air?
"Get some air"?
Your answer to,
"We're sliding headfirst
into a massive crap--"
Hey, hey, hey, Mr. White.
All right, I understand that
the fly is a serious thing now.
All right? I'm on board.
I'm just saying,
you know,
maybe if we went
and got some air
it would help us
come up
with a plan
on how to catch it.
Then come back down here
and subtract his ass.
Oh, wait, do you
have your keys?
Yeah.
You sure? Last thing we
need is to get locked out.
Yeah. Hey!
If you're not gonna help me,
stay out of my way!
Hey!
Yo, yo, does somebody have
an ax I can use? El ax-o!
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
El ax-o!
[CUMBRE NORTEÑA'S "SIMPLEMENTE
AMAME" PLAYING ON RADIO]
[FLY BUZZING]
There we go.
Say good night.
[CLATTERING]
Son of a bitch!
Son of a--
Damn it.
Where in the hell is that...?
What the hell?
[KNOCKING]
Need some juice maybe?
JESSE:
Knock yourself out.
It's a real one.
Yeah, like yours
was working.
No, no, no.
Look, we're trying
to decontaminate.
You don't decontaminate
by contaminating further.
What the hell
is all this?
Here, how about this?
"Non-toxic glue strips."
Yeah, baby.
It's got pheromones,
all right?
I got a butt-load.
We hang them up
all over the place.
It won't be able
to resist.
I sure hope we have enough.
JESSE:
I'm gonna go out on
a limb and say yeah.
WALT:
Do you see him?
How long do you think
you've been awake?
Why do you keep
asking me that?
Just figure, you know,
you could use some coffee,
is all. I know I could.
How about it?
Yeah.
You take cream and sugar?
Black is fine.
Why don't you just
leave him be?
Let the traps do the work.
These pheromones are
supposed to kick ass.
Bet we catch this mofo
any second.
Thank you.
You ever have, like,
a wild animal
trapped in your house?
Not that I can recall, no.
We did,
this one time,
back when it was
my aunt's house,
back before
she died of cancer.
It was a possum.
Big freaky-looking bitch.
Hey, since when did they
change it to "opossum"?
What's up with that?
I mean, when I was coming up,
it was just "possum."
You know, "opossum"
makes it sound
like he's Irish
or something.
I mean, why they gotta go
changing everything?
Whatever.
It's just big rats anyways.
Giant pink-tailed rats
with their pink rat faces.
Totally freaky,
like alien rats.
Actually, it's not so
much that he got trapped,
but he was living there,
you know, under the house.
You could hear him going
from, like, room to room,
always scurrying
around.
Sometimes I'd see him
outside at night
and it would just,
you know, freeze.
I mean,
it's like you're
not looking right
at it, right?
I mean, it thinks
it's fooling you.
That's what
they do.
I mean, they play
dead or whatever.
It's just so lame.
Is there a discernible
point to this story?
A point that
you'll be arriving at
sometime in
the near future?
It was just a total
bitch to get out.
You know,
it took forever.
Guy came, set all these traps
and all and he finally got it.
But my aunt, you know,
she didn't believe it.
I mean, she kept insisting
she could still hear the thing.
I mean, you could not
tell her any different.
She started keeping
an old umbrella,
you know,
by her chair.
Man, she would just bang
on the floor and yell at it.
Even gave it a name.
It was Scrabble.
Yeah, that was it.
You know, "Scrabble,
just knock it off."
Bang, bang, bang.
She got like that
toward the end.
Got obsessive about stuff.
Just got mad about stuff.
We didn't know
what was up.
It wasn't like her
to be that way.
But it turned out
that the cancer
had spread to her brain
and that was why.
It, um, metastasized.
But it was good that
that was when we decided
to take her to the doctor,
because then we knew
what was up.
You know,
got her some treatment.
Meds, so she wasn't
stressing all the time.
It was a lot better after that.
You know, she was a lot happier.
Where the hell is he?
I've been to my
oncologist, Jesse,
just last week.
I'm still in remission.
I'm healthy.
Okay, so good.
Great.
Well...
no end in sight.
That's great.
Well...
I missed it.
There was some perfect moment
and it passed me right by.
I had to have enough
to leave them.
That was the whole point.
I mean, none of this--
None of this makes any sense
if I didn't have enough.
But it had to be
before she found out. Skyler.
It had to be before that.
Perfect moment for what?
To drop dead?
What, you saying
you wanna die?
I'm saying
I've lived too long.
I mean,
you want them to actually
miss you, you know?
You want their memories
of you to be...
But she just won't--
She just won't understand.
I mean, no matter how well
I explain it,
these days,
she just has this--
This--
I mean, I truly
believe there exists
some combination
of words.
There must exist certain words
in a certain specific order
that would explain
all of this,
but with her, I just--
I just can't ever
seem to find them.
Mr. White, how about
you just sit down?
You know, I was thinking maybe
before the fugue state,
but before the fugue state,
I didn't have enough money.
So no, not then.
And plus, my daughter
wasn't born yet.
It had to be after
Holly was born.
Mr. White--
Definitely
before the surgery.
Oh, Christ.
That damn second cell phone.
I mean, how could
I possibly...?
Ah, I know the moment.
It was the night Jane died.
Yeah, I--
I was at home and
we needed diapers,
and so I said I'd go,
but it was just an excuse.
Actually,
that was the night
I brought you your
money, remember?
Yeah, I remember.
But afterward,
I stopped at a bar.
It was odd.
I never do that,
go to a bar alone.
I just walked in,
sat down.
I never told you.
That you went to a bar?
No, I...
I sit down and this man,
this stranger,
he engages me
in conversation.
He's a complete stranger.
But he turns out to be
Jane's father,
Donald Margolis.
What are you
talking about?
Of course, I didn't
know it at the time.
I mean, he was just
some guy in a bar.
I didn't put it together
until after the crash
when he was
all over the news.
Jane's dad.
I mean,
think of the odds.
Once I tried
to calculate them,
but they're astronomical.
I mean, think of the odds
of me going in, sitting down,
that night in that bar
next to that man.
What did you talk about?
Oh...
Water on Mars.
Family.
What about family?
I told him that
I had a daughter
and he told me
he had one too.
Then he said,
"Never give up
on family."
And I didn't.
I took his advice.
The universe is random.
It's not inevitable.
It's simple chaos.
It's subatomic particles
in endless aimless collision.
That's what
science teaches us.
But what is this saying?
What is it
telling us when,
on the very night that
this man's daughter dies,
it's me who's having
a drink with him?
I mean, how can
that be random?
Hey, come on.
Hey, sit down.
No, no. No, it's--
No. No.
No, that was the moment.
That night.
I should never
have left home.
Never gone to your house.
Maybe things would have...
Oh, thought I was--
I was at home watching TV.
It was some--
Some nature program
about elephants.
And Skyler and Holly
were in another room.
I could hear them
on the baby monitor.
She was singing a lullaby.
If I had just lived right up
to that moment,
and not one second more...
[FLY BUZZING]
that would have
been perfect.
[FLY BUZZING]
Yeah. He's not coming down.
Must be Thailand-hot
up there.
That's why he likes it.
Thailand's hot, right?
Yeah.
Then that's why.
Oh, Jesus.
Hey, hey, wait. Here.
[WHEELS ROLLING]
He's not coming down.
He's staying up there forever.
[CLATTERING]
What are you--?
What are you doing?
What do you think?
I'm gonna get that bitch.
No, you're gonna
break your neck.
Yeah, yeah. Just--
WALT:
No, seriously, you're--
This is a bad idea.
[JESSE GRUNTING]
JESSE:
Damn it.
WALT:
Jesse.
Just hold onto it.
Hold it still?
[JESSE GRUNTING]
[FLY BUZZING]
[CREAKING]
Jesse.
I'm sorry.
Sorry for what,
being a lunatic?
I'm sorry about Jane.
Yeah.
Me too.
I mean...
I'm very sorry.
It's not your fault.
It's not mine either.
It's no one's fault,
not even hers.
You know, we are who
we are, Mr. White.
You know, two junkies with
a duffel bag full of cash.
Like you said, we both would've
been dead within a week.
But I miss her, though.
God, I do.
Whoa. Whoa.
Jesse.
Come down.
Wait. I'm so close.
Let it go.
We need to cook.
What about the contamination?
It's all contaminated.
[FLY BUZZING]
JESSE:
All right, well,
I definitely scared him.
Probably stay out of our way.
[FLY BUZZING]
Yeah! Oh, zap!
Somebody got got, yo!
Did you see that, Mr. Wh--?
[WALT SNORING]
Bins are packed?
Bins are packed.
How's the yield?
Two-oh-two and change.
You okay getting home?
Yeah. Better. Thanks.
Mañana, then.
Jesse, come here.
I couldn't chance
saying it inside.
For all I know,
the lab's wired for sound.
That's half a pound
I said we were off by.
Now, I'm not accusing
you, but if...
You understand?
And if they ever found out...
I didn't take shit.
I'm just saying that
I won't be able to protect you.
Who's asking you to?
[FLY BUZZING]
[♪♪♪]