Yo, I thought I was gonna see
some, like, vaginas.
I didn't say she
actually painted vaginas.
I said, some of her paintings
looked like vaginas.
Uh, seriously?
Not even close.
[CHUCKLES]
Georgia O'Keeffe painted
all kinds of stuff.
Oh.
Everyday items,
her surroundings.
Some of it evoked
an erotic nature.
It's who she was.
Not like any vagina
I ever saw.
This chick
have medical issues?
This particular painting...
Mm?
...is of a door.
Any other doors
we can check out? Shh...
Like, real ones or--?
[JESSE SIGHS]
JESSE:
You know, I-- I don't get it.
Why would anyone
paint a picture of a door,
over and over again,
like, dozens of times?
But it wasn't the same.
Uh-- Yeah, it was.
It was the same subject,
but it was different every time.
The light was different,
her mood was different.
She saw something new
every time she painted it.
And that's not psycho
to you?
Well, then why should we do
anything more than once?
Should I just smoke
this one cigarette?
Maybe we should only have sex
once, if it's the same thing.
Whoa, no.
Should we just watch one sunset?
Or live just one day?
Because it's new
every time.
Each time is a different
experience.
Okay, fine.
I guess the, uh--
The cow skull pictures
were cool, but a door?
I will say it again.
A door.
[SNORES]
Why not a door?
Sometimes you get fixated
on something,
and you might not even get why.
You open yourself
up and go with the flow,
wherever the universe takes you.
[SCOFFS]
Okay, so the universe
took her to a door.
And she got all
obsessed with it
and just had
to paint it 20 times
until it was perfect.
No. I wouldn't say that.
Nothing's perfect.
Yeah? Well,
I mean,
some things.
[LAUGHS]
Aww. That was so sweet,
I think I threw up
in my mouth a bit.
[LAUGHS]
You can't admit,
just for once, that I'm right.
Come on. That O'Keeffe lady
kept trying over and over
until that stupid door
was perfect.
No. That door was her home
and she loved it.
To me, that's about making
that feeling last.
[♪♪♪]
[MOTOR HUMMING]
THERAPIST:
All right, here we go.
You ready?
[HANK PANTING]
Come on, give me a step.
Give me one step.
[EXHALES]
Nope. Nope, that's it.
Take me up.
You can do this, Hank.
Come on,
it's supposed to hurt.
Pain is weakness
leaving your body.
Pain is my foot
in your ass, Marie.
If you can get your leg up
there, I say go for it.
Take me up.
THERAPIST: Coffee break.
You rest for a minute,
then we'll try again.
Never mind your coffee break.
Take me up. I'm done. Uhn.
[MOTOR HUMMING]
THERAPIST:
We'll just pick up
where we left off.
Come on, Uncle Hank.
You can do it.
How else are you gonna
get out of here?
Don't you have friends? Jesus,
find something better to do.
I don't need everyone
staring at me
hanging here like
a camel's ball sack.
Hank, he just wants
to be supportive.
It's all right.
I'll be right back, okay?
Be right back.
Gonna get me out of here
sometime today?
MARIE:
Sky?
We got our first bill,
and, you know,
if you're still insistent--
I am.
Prepare yourself.
They're gonna start coming
in weekly like that, so...
Okay.
You're sure you can do this?
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
I'll do that.
What the hell, man?
What, I can't
work a scale now?
This is bullshit.
Just say it.
Just say the words.
You think I'm stealing.
Shh.
[SIGHS]
GROUP LEADER:
Walk with who you are.
That was the phrase my sponsor
used to use with me,
back when I first started
coming to meetings.
It's probably just
a different way
of saying be yourself, right?
But this idea of
"walk" also tells me
that I have to move forward.
Always good advice,
at least for me.
I see we have some new people
here at Group,
a couple new faces.
See some hands? First time?
Great. Welcome.
Maybe we can go around,
introduce ourselves.
Say whatever's on your mind.
How about you?
You wanna start us off?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Yeah. My name is Andrea, uh...
We don't bite. No judgments.
You can be as open and honest
as you wanna be.
Honestly?
I don't wanna be here.
GROUP LEADER:
All right, fair enough.
Who else had their hand up?
Hey, what's up?
My name's Jesse.
Well, hello.
My name's Brandon.
And this is,
I believe, Peter?
Right, I'm Peter.
How are you?
Look, I just, uh, wanted
to give you a heads up.
It's gonna get slower
smuggling product,
with Grandpa Anus
watching every move I make.
But don't worry,
I'll keep it flowing.
Great, right on.
Yeah.
So, uh, how's it selling?
Mad volume?
Yeah, it's, uh...
You know, it's, um...
It's not so good.
What do you mean?
How much have you sold?
I sold a teenth.
One teenth? That's it?
Yeah.
To who?
To him.
Look, it's not so easy
selling to these people.
They're here trying
to better themselves.
[WHISPERING]
There's positivity
and stuff going on here.
[WHISPERING]
I'm out risking my ass
to get product for you two,
and you're too pussy to sell?
You're pathetic.
You know what?
I want it back. All of it.
I'll sell it myself.
BADGER:
Come on. Don't be like that.
Selling to these people,
it's like shooting a baby.
It's not so easy like you think.
I will show you
exactly how easy it is.
[GROUP CHATTERING]
Thank you.
All right.
See you next week.
Oh, hey, sorry.
No, go ahead.
Andrea, right?
Yeah.
Hey, um, my name's Jesse,
and, uh, I don't really
wanna be here either.
Oh, uh...
Sorry.
[WATER BOILING]
Aunt Marie's coming to dinner?
No.
Your dad is.
WALT JR.:
How'd you get her
to sleep so quick?
Are you that boring?
I'm comforting.
I'm a comforting presence.
Sh-sh-sh.
WALT JR.:
Hey, so check it out.
Ah.
See what that means?
Check out the date.
Next Thursday
is officially six months
that I've had my learner's.
Which means I can get
my provisional
and start driving by myself.
[SCOFFS]
Since when? You don't turn
16 for two more months.
It doesn't matter,
it's a provisional.
Look it up. They changed
the law like, 10 years ago.
Yeah, well,
I didn't vote for that.
WALT JR.:
Doesn't matter if you voted
for it, it's the law.
So start thinking about what
kind of car you wanna buy me.
Hmm.
I think I'd be good with either
an old IROC or a 'Stang.
[CHUCKLES]
Ah. A 'Stang. Mm-hm.
How about something with
playing cards in the spokes?
Makes a nice motory sound,
you know?
[MAKES RATTLING SOUND]
[CHUCKLES]
WALT JR.:
Ha, ha. Dad, you're not gonna
get off that easy.
Well, I-- I think
that this is, uh...
We should probably
table this discussion for later.
Your dad and I have
a couple things
we need to talk about, so...
Okay.
A 1971 Mach 1 fastback,
in Grabber Lime
with a shaker hood.
Hmm.
'Stang.
I'll write that down
so we don't forget.
Oh, darn it, no pencil. Oh!
[SKYLER LAUGHS]
What is
"Ice Station Zebra Associates"?
It's a loan out, it's fine.
Whose loan out?
It's fine. Really.
I...
have a guy.
Okay. Um...
Does your guy know the tax code
and regulations in New Mexico?
There's very specific paperwork
that has to be submitted
quarterly.
Yes. My guy is a top...
guy...
Who is he?
Ah...
What's his name?
What are his qualifications?
Walt, this money
has to be unimpeachable
when it reaches Hank and Marie.
And it is. It will be.
But how do I know that?
I mean, you can't even
tell me the man's name.
Jesus, Skyler,
do you really wanna know?
Do you really wanna know?
Really?
[BABY WAILING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[MAN COUGHING]
SAUL:
Hello. Welcome.
What a pleasure
it is to have you.
I'm gonna call you Skyler,
if that's okay.
It's a lovely name.
Reminds me
of a big beautiful sky.
Walt never told me
how lucky he was--
Prior to recent
unfortunate events.
Clearly his taste in women
is the same as
his taste in lawyers,
only the very best with just
the right amount of dirty.
[CHUCKLING]
That's a joke. That's a joke.
It's funny because you are
so clearly very classy.
Here, please, sit down.
So Walt tells me
that you, uh, have
some concerns I can alleviate.
Uh, yes, I do. I have...
concerns. Um...
If we're going
to go down this road,
and clearly we are for the sake
of my brother-in-law--
I've heard about him. Uh--
He's an American hero.
At any rate,
I need some assurances
that we're gonna go about this
in a manner that is extremely
safe and cautious.
Fair enough. I'll walk you
through the process.
First step is something
we like to call
money laundering, all right?
Uh, uh... Saul.
Take your money, represented by
these jelly beans--
You know, I'm a bookkeeper,
so I actually--
I know what money laundering is.
Uh-huh. Well. Huh.
SKYLER:
Yeah.
And, uh, as with most things,
the devil is in the details.
So to begin with,
what are we saying
is the source of this money?
That's simple. Uh...
Walt here, actually
came up with a great story
about gambling winnings.
Blackjack, right?
Some card-counting system?
Um-- Well, actually
that was Skyler's idea.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Well, you grow more gorgeous
by the minute.
Well, there you have it. Uh--
I'll generate false
Currency Transaction Reports
out the wazoo,
as well as the necessary W-2Gs.
I know a couple casino managers
who will jump at the chance
to report false losses.
It's a win-win for everyone.
Yeah, but you can't
sell that for very long--
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Way ahead of you. Uh...
We declare just enough
so as not to arouse suspicion,
then Walt's onetime winnings
become seed money
for an investment.
Investment in what?
Drum roll, please. Wait for it.
Laser tag.
Laser tag. Seven thousand square
feet of rollicking fun
in the heart of northern
Bernalillo County.
Laser tag?
Yeah, there's guns
and glow lights,
and kids wear the vests--
Yeah, no, no. I-- Right.
No, no. I actually--
I know what it is. It's just
in relation to Walt, it's...
[LAUGHS]
I mean, it doesn't make
any sense.
Makes more sense than
you two being together.
I'm still trying
to figure out that.
Do you even know Walt? I mean,
how would he, of all people
buy a laser tag business?
It-- It doesn't add up.
It adds up perfectly.
Walt's a scientist,
scientists love lasers.
Plus, they got
bumper boats, so...
"Hey, everybody,
"Walt suddenly decided
to invest in laser tag.
Just out of the blue."
Really? That's what
we're supposed to tell people,
our family, our friends,
the government?
Let me bottom line this.
You don't need
to be involved, okay?
Because I've been doing
this a lot of years,
successfully, believe it or not,
without your help.
So, heh, thank you
for stopping by.
You want a beer or something?
Or something?
What do you mean?
Heh.
Like, beer. Heh.
I'm cleaned out
of anything else.
Even if I wasn't,
we're not supposed to.
Yeah.
I've heard it over and over
and over again.
You know, don't you think
it's ridiculous
that society says beer is okay
and a little hit
of something sweet is wrong?
I mean, what's the point of
shutting yourself off completely
from something
that lifts you off the ground?
[SIGHS]
I spend so much energy
fighting the urge not to use
and I feel like crap
because of it.
I know, it's just...
What?
I can't get caught using again.
See, the thing is,
not to get caught.
You ever try that blue stuff
that's going around?
[SIGHS]
Just a little gas in the tank
and suddenly
everything is interesting.
Man, I wish I could make
that feeling last.
Like I said,
I got nothing here.
What if I could get some?
[DOOR OPENS]
Mommy, Mommy.
Hey, baby.
Your nana brought
you home early.
Grandma, I thought
you were keeping Brock today?
I was, then I saw your car.
I thought you had a meeting.
I did,
but we changed the time.
Grandma, this is Jesse.
He's from the meeting.
He's like a sponsor.
Jesse, this is Grandma.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Jesse, this is Brock.
So you, uh,
have a kid, huh?
What's up?
Brock, huh?
That's a cool name.
Here, give it up.
[CHUCKLES]
Brock is almost 6.
You okay, with kids?
What? Yeah. Yeah, he's cool.
Okay, Brock is gonna
go play in his room
while the big people talk.
He's gonna go play
with his Legos and his cars.
Say, "Bye, Jesse."
Bye, Jesse.
ANDREA:
Hope you had a good time
at Grandma's.
Oh, I fixed your blue car,
do you remember?
The convertible one?
You can jump on your bed.
Play with your toys.
Safe and cautious, that's
all I'm asking and that man
is neither.
I'll admit he comes across
like a circus clown,
but he actually knows
what he's doing.
And safe and cautious is you not
being involved in this at all.
Well, it's a little
late on that.
This is what happens
when you decide
to pay our bills
with drug money.
Skyler,
this isn't just about
what happened before.
My involvement
in this is ongoing.
Understand?
I can't just quit.
I have, uh,
something of a contract.
But it's all very safe,
professional.
Structured.
Like, I can't simply quit.
Where you going?
If you're gonna launder money,
Walt,
at least do it right.
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
SKYLER:
You worked here four years.
It's a business you understand.
It's a story people
will believe.
Not laser tag, this.
This is what we buy.
You.
This is what you buy.
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
Yeah, I mean,
there's free donuts.
Nothing's wrong
with a free donut.
Hey, um, Jesse, right?
Brandon, Peter.
How goes it? Hanging in there?
Can we please, just--?
Dumb-ass.
Sorry, man. I was trying
to keep it on the DL.
So you and that girl,
do the deed yet?
Do what?
You know, sell to her?
What are you two
even doing here?
What do you mean?
You can't get
your nut up to sell,
what's the point of even coming?
Homey, I'm on, like,
step five.
Deuce, yo. I'm catching up.
Whatever. Later.
Hey.
Dude needs to come
into the fold.
BADGER:
Yup.
[SPANISH MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey, you know what?
I have magical powers.
You wanna see?
Ready?
That's not real.
It is real. All right,
do you wanna see something real?
Look at this. Watch this.
Ready?
You like that?
That's science and stuff,
makes it do that.
Do it again.
Let Jesse eat his dinner, Brock.
Oh, it's okay. It's okay.
Wanna see it again?
Could you do a trick
with firecrackers?
Firecrackers? Um...
You know, I don't have
any firecrackers on me.
Who does tricks
with firecrackers?
Tomas.
Tomas does tricks with
firecrackers, huh? Who's Tomas?
He's my kid brother.
Yeah?
And we don't
talk about him.
Come on, eat your food, Brock.
JESSE:
Can I have a chip?
I'm gonna steal your chip.
BROCK:
Hey, that's mine.
SAUL:
That's it?
That's what you wanna buy?
WALT:
People will believe it,
at least.
I worked here for four years.
"Wax on, wax off,"
was that you?
Hey, how come you guys
always give air freshener?
I explicitly say,
"I want no air freshener"
and every time, I drive away
smelling like
an Alpine whorehouse.
All due respect, I don't see it.
So I vote-- I vote no.
It makes a better story
than your laser tag.
Is that you talking
or Yoko Ono?
She has a point.
It makes more sense
that I invest right here.
Based on her years of experience
in money laundering, I suppose.
Let me tell you something.
If you're committed enough,
you can make any story work.
I once convinced a woman
that I was Kevin Costner,
and it worked because
I believed it, all right?
Has nothing to do
with the story.
Besides, this dump
isn't gonna work
because it doesn't have a Danny.
There's no Danny here.
What in God's name is a Danny?
Danny runs the laser tag.
Danny is the guy
who had a vision.
Where others saw a dirt lot,
he saw black lights,
rubber aliens,
teenagers running around
with ray guns, right?
Like Bugsy Siegel
in the desert.
And when the stock market
took a shit
and Danny got into trouble,
he went searching for exactly
the type of situation
that we're offering.
Danny will look the other way
to keep his dream afloat.
In other words,
Danny can be trusted completely.
That guy,
the guy with the, uh--
The eyebrows that won't quit,
is he a Danny?
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
You buy this place, all you got
is a big building
that squirts water.
You got no Danny here.
[SIGHS]
You wanna stay for dinner?
Yeah.
Thanks.
What time is it?
Early still.
So...
[CHUCKLES]
What?
Thought maybe if you're holding,
we can do something.
What?
You know, that blue stuff
you were talking about.
Maybe you had a line on some?
Wait.
Whoa. What?
Thought you said
the kid is coming home.
Yeah,
in a few hours.
And you seriously
wanna get high?
I don't know what
you're getting so pissed about.
You're the one who
brought it up the other day.
Yeah, that was before
I found out you got a kid.
What kind of mother are you?
What?
You heard me.
What kind of mom gets wasted
with a little kid
to take care of?
Nobody can say
I don't take care of my son.
You gonna come in my house
and judge me?
You got no responsibilities so
it's okay for you to get high?
Lo--
What do you know about me?
I take care of my baby.
I'll do anything for him.
The day Brock was born,
I swore,
I won't let what happened
to Tomas, happen to my son.
I'll die first.
Sorry. I--
I just...
Look, I'll-- I'll get
out of here if you want.
That's what you wanna do,
then go.
It's not what I want.
Look, I was out of line
talking about that stuff.
[SIGHS]
We both were.
You're right,
I don't know what
you've been through.
You can tell me if you want.
This whole neighborhood's
run by gangs.
They run the drugs,
control the streets.
They sort of took Tomas in.
No dad around.
Eight years old,
they got Tomas slinging.
Part of some crew.
Then when he was 10,
for some initiation
or something,
they made him kill somebody.
I heard the rumors.
I didn't believe it at first.
But then I saw him
like a week later.
And he told me,
yeah, he did it.
They gave Tomas a gun.
Gave him a choice.
Him or some dude.
So he did it.
Told me all about it
like it was nothing.
Who did he say he killed?
Some dealer.
From some outside crew.
Right around the corner
from here, over off of Central.
Just rode up on his bike
and shot him.
Off of Central?
Like over by
the train tracks?
When was this?
Few months back.
What else did he tell you?
He shot the guy
right through the neck.
Shot him dead.
Just because he was working
the wrong corner.
It won't happen again.
Not to my son.
Guess what.
People who say "guess what"
and then actually expect you
to guess,
I hate those people.
Well, I just heard
about a certain patient
named Schrader-comma-Hank
who is going to be released
at the end of this week.
Isn't that fantastic?
They plan on rolling me
out the front door?
Or put me on a greased plank
and slide me out the window?
Hey.
Because I don't care
what any damned
insurance company thinks.
I'm not leaving here
till I'm well.
Hank, this isn't
about insurance.
I've talked to everybody,
and they all say you are
healthy enough to go home.
Oh, I'm healthy enough, huh?
Yeah.
Hank, you get
stronger every day.
You don't need
to be in a hospital.
In this condition,
yeah, I do.
You'll be just as comfortable
at home as you are here.
You'll have
all the same equipment.
Same equipment?
What's that mean?
The equipment
that you have here,
that you need.
Short-term.
You'll do your PT at home,
and it'll be great
because you'll be home.
Wait till you see the bedroom.
I had them move the plasma in.
I know that's how
you always wanted it.
You only had to get
shot to get it, right?
I got you a new bed--
A hospital bed?
Well--
You put a hospital bed
in my bedroom?
Hank,
you'll be home.
You get that out of my house.
You hear me, Marie?
Today.
Hank--
I leave this hospital,
when I walk out of here.
You understand?
And not before.
SKYLER:
Wha--? What's a Danny?
Danny's an accomplice.
Someone who's in on the scheme,
who knows about laundering,
who's paid to look
the other way.
Now, while I agree with you
that laser tag is a hard sell,
without a Danny, the car wash
isn't really an option.
And he can't get you another
Danny to run the car wash?
Easier said than done.
If we're looking
for someone trustworthy.
[SIGHS]
What about me?
What about you?
Me.
I'll be the Danny.
No. No, no, Skyler,
that is not a good idea.
I'm perfectly capable
of managing a small business.
A legal business, not this.
Who else could we trust?
No.
Walt,
I'm in this.
And if I'm in it, I'm gonna
do it right.
No.
You are not in this.
You are not--
We're married,
how am I not in this?
We are not married, Skyler,
we're divorced.
Right?
I never actually got around
to filing the papers.
Married couples
can't be compelled
to testify against one another.
So there's that.
[WHIRRING]
Jesse. Jesse.
Respirator.
Right.
[PHONE RINGING]
Yes?
Uh-huh.
Yes, all right.
Okay.
Yeah,
I'll be there.
What was that?
An invitation.
[RINGS DOORBELL]
Ah. Walter,
you're right on time.
Please, come in.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING OVER STEREO]
I hope you like
paila marina.
It's a fancy name
for fish stew.
It sounds like a cliché,
but indeed,
it's just like my mother
used to make it.
Come on. You can help me cook.
This is a Chilean dish
that I love,
but I never get to make it.
Kids won't eat it.
But, uh,
you know how that is.
Sure.
Do you mind?
Would-- Would you
slice the garlic?
Very thin.
Why did you
invite me here?
We're working together,
why not break bread together?
Now, the garlic?
[LIGHT SPANISH MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO]
Mm.
It always amazes me
the way the senses work
in connection to memory.
I mean, this stew is simply
an amalgam of ingredients.
Taken separately,
these ingredients alone
don't remind me of anything.
I mean,
not very much at all.
But in this precise combination,
the smell of this meal,
instantly, it brings you
back to my childhood.
How is that possible?
Basically, it takes place
in the hippocampus.
Neural connections
are formed.
The senses make the neurons
express signals
that go right back to the same
part of the brain as before.
Where memory is stored.
It's, uh, something called
relational memory.
Um... Heh.
Don't quote me on that,
I'm...
I'm rusty on my biology.
That's very interesting.
Walter,
I would like to help you,
if I could.
Help me how?
Well, when I first started out,
I made a lot of mistakes.
More than I care to admit.
I wish I'd had someone
to advise me,
because this life of ours,
it can overwhelm.
You are a wealthy man now.
And one must learn
to be rich.
To be poor,
anyone can manage.
What advice
do you have for me?
Never make
the same mistake twice.
Hey.
What's up?
You, uh..? You Tomas?
I heard you were the man.
Yeah, what you want?
Um...
Crystal.
You think you could hook me up?
Three hundred.
For a teenth?
Shit, come on, yo.
Three hundred.
[♪♪♪]
JESSE:
Hey, what's up?
Hey, yo.
Bounce.
[♪♪♪]