[♪♪♪]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Well, hello there.
SKYLER:
Hi, I hope we're not too late.
No, no. Perfect timing.
Okay.
Stan, this is my husband, Walt.
Hi.
Good to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Sandia Laboratories, huh?
Yeah.
I hear some fascinating stuff
goes on out there.
Yeah, well, you know.
Heh, heh.
Working on anything
you can talk about?
I'm picturing giant space
lasers. Am I right?
Honestly, what I do
would bore you senseless.
Giant space lasers?
Now, that sounds cool.
I'll bring it up
at our next staff meeting.
Well, just remember I get a cut.
All right. It's a deal.
So this is it, honey.
What do you say?
You wanna take a tour?
Sure.
Okay.
Look, how about
I give y'all some privacy?
I'll go out to the car,
make a few calls.
Take as much time as you need.
All right.
Okay, thanks.
He's a nice guy.
He doesn't push.
Yeah.
So as you can see,
there's this, uh,
kind of flow going on here.
It's a nice big living room.
Yeah.
And, um,
this is the dining area.
Oh, the dining area. Right.
Yes. Oh, and, uh...
it's got a pool.
Ah, pool is nice.
Mm-hm.
Backyard could be
a little bigger.
And-- Oh, there's a
breakfast bar
kind of dealie here,
which is nice.
And, um, I don't know,
the kitchen's really spacious
and, you know,
got good appliances and...
How many bedrooms?
Three. Told you.
They're all pretty good
size and--
Oh, this is the first
one here.
And then there's two more
at the back.
Only three bedrooms?
We're gonna need at least
five, don't you think?
Five?
Yeah.
What, do I look like
I'm about to drop a litter?
No, no, no. We'll have three
kids total, eventually.
Yeah, but we'll need
a spare room for a study,
so that I can work at home
and you can write, huh?
Yeah, no. I don't think
this is gonna be enough.
Okay, um,
what about a wine cellar?
[IN BRITISH ACCENT]
I mean, we certainly
cannot be expected
to live without
a wine cellar.
Very funny. I just think we need
to set our sights high is all.
At least,
higher than here.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Walt, this is
a good neighborhood.
It's got a good elementary
and, supposedly,
a very good high school,
and believe me, because I have
definitely looked everywhere.
For our price range,
this is as good as it gets.
Well, then let's stretch
our price range.
Truly. I mean, why...?
Why buy a starter house
when we'll have to move out
in a year or two?
Did you win the lottery
and not tell me?
I'm serious.
Come on.
Why be cautious?
We've got nowhere to go
but up.
[♪♪♪]
[SIGHS]
[PHONE RINGING]
Yeah.
MIKE: Walter, you see us?
Yeah. I see you.
I'd like you
to exit your vehicle
and start walking
toward us.
And then what?
I'm gonna need some...
Some kind of assurance.
I assure you, I could
kill you from way over here
if it makes you feel
any better.
[♪♪♪]
Walter,
you've been busy.
You wanna put your arms out to
your sides for me, if you would?
You know I haven't slept
since Thursday?
I was out all night
cleaning up after you.
I need my sleep.
You said no half measures.
Yeah. Funny how words can be
so open to interpretation.
You get your car fixed?
Not yet.
MIKE:
You're gonna wanna
get your car fixed.
WALT:
Let's see how this goes first.
[♪♪♪]
Has your condition
worsened?
Excuse me?
Your medical condition.
Has it grown worse?
Not that I know of, no.
Is there a ringing
in your ears?
Are you seeing bright lights
or hearing voices?
I'm quite well, thank you.
GUS:
No. Clearly, you are not.
No rational person would do
as you have done.
Explain yourself.
My partner was about
to get himself shot.
I intervened.
Some worthless junkie.
For him, you intervene
and put us all at risk.
Some contemptible junkie
who couldn't keep the peace
for eight hours.
That's right. He couldn't.
He was angry because
those two dealers of yours
had just murdered
an 11-year-old boy.
I heard about it.
He should have
let me take care of them.
Maybe.
Then again, maybe he thought
it was you who gave the order.
Are you asking me
if I ordered
the murder of a child?
I would never ask you that.
Where is Pinkman now?
I wouldn't know.
Couple of time zones away,
at least.
Beyond that,
I'd only be guessing.
He has enough money
to last forever,
he knows he needs
to keep moving.
You'll never
find him.
I don't know,
Walt,
it's what I do,
after all.
He's out of the picture.
I saved his life,
I owed him that,
but now he and I are done,
which is exactly what you
wanted, isn't it?
[SIGHS]
You've always struck me
as a very pragmatic man.
So if I may, I would like
to review options with you.
Of which, it seems to me,
you have two.
Option A:
You kill me right here and now.
Apparently, I have made
that very easy for you.
You can kill me,
no witnesses,
and then spend the next few
weeks or months
tracking down Jesse Pinkman,
and you kill him too.
A pointless exercise, it seems
to me, but that is option A.
What is option B?
I continue cooking.
You and I both forget
about Pinkman.
We forget this
ever happened.
We consider this
a lone hiccup
in an otherwise long and
fruitful business arrangement.
I prefer option B.
You'd need a new assistant.
I could get right on that.
No.
This time, I choose.
Your car,
get it fixed.
Yeah.
[DOOR RATTLING]
Really?
It's good to see you.
Thanks.
It's good to be back.
Well, shall we?
By all means, Gale,
let's cook.
MIKE:
What about that rhinoceros?
You think he'd make a good pet?
GIRL: No.
MIKE: No?
Don't you think
if you called to him,
he'd come running
for his supper?
I bet he would.
I bet he'd come running:
Boom-duh-boom-duh-boom.
You're silly, Pop-Pop.
Well, a little. But he'd
probably knock everything over.
Plus, there's that
big nose of his.
That's not a nose,
that's a horn.
Is that so?
His real nose is little.
Hm.
I learn all kinds of things
being with you.
Okay, June bug,
these are for you.
What about the rest?
The rest are for me.
No, they're not.
You're too old for balloons.
[GROANS]
You're never too old
for balloons. Give me a hug.
I see your mama.
Don't keep her waiting.
Bye, Pop-Pop.
Bye, baby.
WOMAN:
Hi, sweetie.
Did you have fun with Pop-Pop?
[♪♪♪]
[BEEPING]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[BOTH SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SILENCED GUNSHOTS]
[SILENCED GUNSHOT]
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
Please. Please, no.
Argh!
[♪♪♪]
Chow, you have anything
you wanna tell me?
Thank God you're here.
They keep me prisoner.
They keep you prisoner.
I don't do nothing
for them ever.
They try and make me.
I say, no.
They steal my chemicals.
I can't stop them.
I am businessman.
You're a business--
The lady out front--
Hey, lady, are you still there?
Ask her if she's still there.
[SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN CHINESE]
She says, yes.
How's her driving? Driving.
Is she good behind the wheel?
Good. She's good driver.
Licensed? Dependable?
She has a Camry.
Good.
Ah!
[GRUNTING]
The trucks will be here
first thing in the morning.
I strongly recommend that
you return our calls next time.
So have her drive you
to the hospital.
[CHOW GRUNTING]
She's gonna need her shoe.
[CHOW WHIMPERING]
Where'd they cross?
Laredo, looks like.
They didn't exactly send
their A players.
But like you said,
it's cartel, all right.
Probing for weakness.
Hm.
Well, they didn't find any.
What about Pinkman?
I'm making inquiries.
[LIQUID GURGLING]
WALT:
Yeah, that's two.
All right, let's close it up.
All right, bring it down.
You ready?
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
[MACHINE BEEPING]
Okay, we're good.
You can take
your mask off now.
GALE:
Does that guy ever leave?
When exactly did
that start?
It's new.
We had a, uh...
We had a little drama
with the person you replaced.
Sorry to hear that.
No, it'll be fine.
Things will continue
to smooth out and, uh...
Yeah, it'll be fine.
By the way, if you're at all
worried about working with me--
No, I'm not.
Because whatever
my shortcomings last time,
I intend for things to go
perfectly from here on out.
So if there is--?
Gale, you're great.
Seriously.
I just...
However you like things
to be done
is exactly how we're gonna
do them.
Period.
From here on out, so...
Please, teach me.
Okay.
[MELLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
ON STEREO]
[MAN SINGING IN ITALIAN ON
STEREO AND GALE SINGING ALONG]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[STEREO TURNS OFF]
Gale. It's good to see you.
Mr. Fring.
Wow, this is--
I should have called first.
I'm not interrupting anything,
am I?
No. No, no, not at all.
Please, come in.
Can I offer you something?
A crème de menthe?
No. No, thank you.
I'm sorry
for the inconvenience.
Oh, no, no.
It's no inconvenience.
I need to talk to you
about something.
Something rather
pressing.
If push came to shove,
I was wondering
how soon you might be able
to take over the lab yourself.
You and an assistant.
Why would--?
Why would push come to shove?
Has Walter ever
talked to you
about why he got into
this particular line of work?
Uh...
I guess I assumed
it was because it pays so well.
It is,
but specifically,
has he ever spoken to you
about his health problems?
I'm not surprised.
He's a very private person.
What exactly
are his health problems?
He's dying of cancer.
It is why he does this,
to provide for his family,
which he's accomplished.
They will never want for
anything. He's seen to that.
How long does he have?
That is very much the question.
He does not wanna talk about it.
And every time I bring it up
with him...
I don't know that he's fully
accepted the reality of it.
And not to sound cold-blooded,
but I am running
a business here.
No, I understand.
I have a very large
investment in this.
There's so much overhead that
I can't afford to shut down.
Not even for a week.
So you understand my concern.
And my desire for continuity.
I do. Absolutely.
Now, I intend to keep Walter on
as long as he wants,
assuming that he's physically
up to it.
But as he cannot or will not
tell me how long that might be,
I must prepare
for the worst-case scenario.
Well,
worst-case scenario...
Uh...
I suppose if we had
at least a few more cooks
together.
You don't think
you're ready now?
Well, I mean,
he is such a...
A master.
There's always more
for me to learn.
But I'm thinking
that if we had,
say,
one or two more cooks.
One more...
I guess would do it.
I suppose.
I believe in you, Gale.
I know that when the time comes,
you will be ready.
What's up?
Walt, is there--?
Um...
Any particular trick
to purging the catalyst bed?
No, it's pretty straightforward.
I'll show you when we get there.
[SIGHS]
[HEADSET BEEPS]
Yeah?
Tell him I'm in conference.
[POP MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS
IN ADJACENT ROOM]
Can't you see I'm in conference?
MIKE:
I'm looking to find a client.
I was hoping you could help me
out with an address.
Which client?
Jesse Pinkman.
Jesse-Pinkman-in-the-phone-book
Jesse Pinkman. Hm.
How would one track him down,
I wonder.
[MASSAGER TURNS OFF]
You're still here.
I need your full
attention, Saul.
Jesse Pinkman.
Current whereabouts.
The sooner you tell me,
the sooner you get back to
whatever the hell
this is exactly.
What am I, an 8th-grade hall
monitor? Current whereabouts.
Let me tell you something,
Mike, you--
Whoa, you are good
right there.
Now, let's both get
comfortable.
Now, when I say,
I'm looking for Pinkman,
we both know why,
don't we?
You pretending otherwise
only wastes my time
and serves to annoy me.
Look, Mike,
there are rules
to this, uh, lawyer thing.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Attorney-client privilege.
That's a big one.
And that's something
I provide for you.
So if I give up Pinkman,
well, then you're gonna be
asking,
"Old Saul gives them up
pretty easy.
What's to keep him
from giving me up?"
You see? So then,
where's the trust?
I trust the hole in the desert
I'd leave you in.
Yeah, that's an argument.
Saul,
don't make me beat you
till your legs don't work.
Now tell me where to find him.
You know it's the right thing.
I can't tell you, Mike,
all right? I...
Look, if I was to tell you,
well, I just--
I couldn't live with myself.
I'm sorry.
But who's to say I didn't write
the address down
in my day planner?
Or on a scratch piece of paper
somewhere?
Who's to say
I didn't write down a location
strictly for
my own professional use?
Do not touch anything
on my desk.
I'm gonna leave the room,
make myself a Nescafé.
SAUL:
I'm just looking out for you,
that's all. Like a mother hen.
Believe me, money-laundering
ain't what it used to be.
God, do I miss the '80s.
You're wasting your time.
I'm buying the car wash,
end of story.
Well, one look at this place,
you're gonna fall in love, so...
Heh, heh. Huh?
Was I right?
Where else you gonna find
a cash-only business
that's this fun?
Unless we're talking massage
parlors, and, uh,
I don't see it.
Shall we?
SAUL:
You ever actually play
laser tag?
You know, it's good cardio.
Plus, you get to shoot at kids.
Heh.
SAUL:
You got your bumper cars
over there down that way.
Got your arcade here,
all the latest video games.
Snack bar's there.
Nothing stopping you
from selling beer
to the parents.
That's a whole new
revenue stream--
WALT:
All right, already.
We're good.
Holy Christ.
We're good? This constitutes
good where you're from?
My car is bugged?
I said, maybe. Maybe bugged.
I'm being followed? What the
hell have you gotten me into?
My own PI is threatening
to break my legs.
That's like Thomas Magnum
threatening that little prissy
guy with the mustache.
Over and above. Service-wise,
this is over and above.
You and I survive this,
oh, I'm seriously rethinking
my pricing, yeah.
And that goes double for you,
Hip-Hop.
Okay, my guy's no dummy,
right?
So I give us maybe 24 hours
before he figures out
that address goes nowhere.
You guys do your thing,
make it snappy.
I'll go see if they have
"Tetris" or something.
So how you holding up?
Hm.
You?
I got my old job back.
At least until they kill me
and Gale takes over.
So he's their boy, huh?
He's their boy.
How long you think
you've got?
Well, he asks a lot of questions
about the cooking process.
I try to be as vague
as possible,
but I got that guy Victor
watching me,
listening to every word I say.
You know, maybe that
the only thing saving me
is Gale's fastidiousness.
And once he feels confident that
he knows my entire method...
So, what do we do?
You know what we do.
There's got to be
some other way.
Maybe it's better for you
to just go to the cops.
All right? I mean, I can't
believe I'm saying that and all,
but for your family.
Hey,
the DEA would love you,
all the shit you could
tell them.
Federal witness protection,
that's a good deal.
As for me, I'll hit the road,
yo. I mean, I'll make it.
We had a good run.
But it's over.
Never the DEA.
The cook can't stop.
That's the one thing
I'm certain of,
production cannot stop.
Gus can't afford to.
So if I'm the only chemist
that he's got,
then I've got leverage,
and leverage keeps me alive.
It keeps you alive too.
I think I can see to that.
If I'm the only chemist
that he's got.
I can't do it, Mr. White.
Like you said, I'm...
I'm not a...
I can't do it.
I'll do it.
I'm gonna need your help.
I mean, they're watching me
day and night.
They never leave me alone
with Gale, not for a moment.
Hell, I don't even know
where the man lives.
He's not in the phone book,
I can't find him
on the Internet,
and I can't do it in the lab,
Victor's always there.
But if I could just
shake Victor,
for even an hour one night,
I think then that
I may be able to...
make it look like
an accident.
There's got to be
some other way.
I'm all ears.
But when it comes down to you
and me versus him, I'm sorry.
I'm truly sorry,
but it's gonna be him.
Now, you are the only edge
that I've got,
as long as they don't know
that you're in town.
But I need you to track him,
get me his address.
And I'll do the rest.
Look, I saved your life, Jesse.
Are you gonna save mine?
[♪♪♪]
[PHONE VIBRATING]
[LINE RINGING]
JESSE:
Yeah?
Please, tell me you found him.
6353 Juan Tabo Boulevard.
Apartment 6.
You there?
Yeah.
6353 Juan Tabo. Number 6.
Got it.
He's home?
Yep.
Anyone watching the place?
No. Looks pretty much
wide-open.
When are you gonna do it?
Tonight.
Once it gets dark.
Don't do this, Mr. White.
Please. Go to the cops.
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
VICTOR:
We got a problem.
Some kind of chemical leaking
in your lab.
Better come with me.
I'll, uh-- I'll follow you.
They tell me to bring you,
I bring you.
Come on,
get in the car.
[♪♪♪]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
I don't know if it's
a barrel leak or what,
but you got something
mighty stinky down there.
After you.
Walter, the sooner you figure
out what this is,
the sooner we all
go home.
Please, don't do this.
Mike,
you don't have to do this.
Yeah, unfortunately, I do,
Walter.
Downstairs.
I'll cook. I'll cook for free.
There won't be any more trouble,
I promise you.
No.
If I could just talk to Gus--
I can make him understand.
If I could talk to Gus,
I can convince him.
Just let me, please--
Please!
Please, let me talk to him!
Shut up! Shut up.
I can't do it. I'm sorry.
I'll give you Jesse Pinkman.
Okay? Like you said,
he's the problem.
He's always been
the problem.
And without him, we would--
And he's in town, all right?
He's not in Virginia or wherever
the hell you're looking for him.
He's right here in Albuquerque
and I could take you to him.
I'll take you right to him. Huh?
What do you say?
Where is he?
Right now, you give me
an address.
I don't-- He moves.
He moves around.
But if you let me call him--
No, no, please.
No, I just-- My phone.
I'll just--
It's just my phone. I'll call
him, and I'll have him meet me.
All right? Okay?
Okay?
[LIGHTER CLICKING]
[PHONE VIBRATING]
Did you do it?
Mr. White?
No, I didn't do it.
I can't now.
It's gonna have to be you.
What? No way, man.
Listen to me.
You're closer than we are.
You'll have a 20-minute lead.
They've got me at the laundry.
They're going to kill me.
Jesse, do it now!
Son of a bitch!
WALT:
Do it, Jesse! Do it!
Huh.
Just what the hell
was that exactly?
You might wanna hold off.
Yeah? Why?
Because your boss
is gonna need me.
6353 Juan Tabo,
Apartment 6.
Yeah.
[CHINESE MUSIC BLARING
ON STEREO AND KETTLE WHISTLING]
[PHONE VIBRATING]
[WHISTLING STOPS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[VIBRATING]
[STEREO TURNS OFF]
Hi. How can I help you?
[WHIMPERING]
GALE:
Take whatever you want.
I have money. I have--
I got a lot of money.
I have...
Please, don't do this.
You don't-- You...
You-- You don't have
to do this.
[♪♪♪]