[MAN EXHALES SHARPLY]
[MIKE BREATHING HEAVILY]
[♪♪♪]
[TRUCK RATTLING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[AIR BRAKES HISS]
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
[♪♪♪]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
[MAN 1 SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MAN 2 SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAN 2:
You want me to open the doors?
[MAN 1 SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAN 2:
Here. The keys. Take them.
[MAN 1 SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAN 1:
Why you talking?
[MAN 1 SPEAKING SPANISH]
MAN 2:
No! No, no, no--
[GUNSHOT THEN BODY HITS GROUND]
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOT]
[GUNFIRE]
[GUNSHOTS]
[SHELL CASINGS CLATTER]
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Gambling destroyed my life.
Me, my family,
everything I loved.
It was like a robbery,
only I was the thief.
It's amazing the stories
you tell yourself to justify it.
The lies that lead you
to just one more hand,
one more spin,
one more roll of the dice.
This is our deal, okay?
Marie, no.
You guys are not
lifting a finger. I mean it.
We're bringing everything. So--
This is not up for debate.
Great.
Sweetie, don't worry.
We're not gonna say one word
about the bills.
We just wanna bring everyone
up to speed.
All right, I'll see you soon.
Bye.
[SIGHS]
So...
Tonight's the night.
No turning back.
Well...
Okay.
Let's do this.
WALT:
Okay. So first,
I assign point values.
Correlate
to the effect of removal.
You're gonna split the eights?
Skyler, please.
Now, the mathematical principle
known as the Kelly Criterion,
upon which I devised
my own strategy--
Not dissimilar
to the MIT system--
Walt, you're not
teaching them.
You wanted me to be thorough.
Play. You're taking too long.
You don't think it behooves me
to be able to explain this?
It behooves you to be a pro,
that's all.
That's the fiction.
So, chop-chop.
Don't chop-chop me.
Now, we both know
that the first decision
is whether or not to split
or to surrender.
On eights. Split them.
Good on both.
Next decision is whether
to double down or not.
Which you should be doing.
On an 11, yes. Double.
WALT:
Okay, this hand over here,
we have a soft 18.
The final decision is whether
or not to hit or to stand.
Hit it.
Becomes a hard 15.
Dealer has a nine.
I see that.
Hit it.
Oh.
Okay, let's see what I got.
And 21.
Damn.
Yup.
Okay, the key thing
to remember here
is that it's not about
any one hand.
The key is the number
of hands per hour.
Mm. Let's go again.
Zero, minus one, 0.6.
Okay.
[TAPS ON TABLE]
Walt.
It's not as if
I don't know how to play.
I certainly more than understand
how to count cards.
Let's just keep going.
No, you know what?
I'm in recovery, remember?
I shouldn't even be playing.
And that is the fiction
that we should be sticking to.
You know what?
You're right. Yeah.
Wow.
Okay. Um...
We're not leaving
anything to chance.
All right. Let's get started.
Got a lot of...
Walt. We got
a lot of ground to cover.
What is this?
We have to get
our story straight.
We've gotta be
on the same page.
A script?
Bullet points.
Bullet points?
We got a novella.
This is smart. You really
wanna try to sell a DEA agent
some full-of-holes story
about how we have enough money
to buy a car wash?
Am I supposed to memorize this?
We need to practice.
We need to be word-perfect.
Within reason.
We need this story to be
solid and sympathetic
and, most of all,
completely believable.
The story that
you already told Marie.
You think
she hasn't told Hank?
Ha. Come on, this is Marie
we're talking about here.
No, she hasn't.
[SCOFFS]
She hasn't.
Hank thinks his insurance
is paying for everything.
Marie's not telling him
we're paying his therapy bills.
And neither are we.
And why is that again?
Really?
If we have
the gambling story...
Did you take money, Walt?
You remember
Gretchen and Elliot?
I seem to recall you'd rather
sell drugs than take help.
Fine.
Marie will tell Hank
in her own time.
And at least we'll have laid
the groundwork.
And coming clean
with Hank and Juni--
Appearing to come clean will be
the best thing for everyone.
We talked about this.
Okay? We agreed about this.
Yes, we did. It's just...
What?
Never mind. Just--
Okay. So...
I really think we should
tag team the narrative, okay?
We'll each be responsible
for certain portions
of the story and then we can--
We can hand off
so we don't leave anything out,
and it'll seem natural.
Okay. So I'm gonna launch
with the exciting news
that we are buying
a car wash.
Yay.
The next logical question
Hank will probably ask is:
"Where are you
getting the money?"
To which I'll say:
We wanna tell you
the whole story.
It's a doozy,
so hold onto your hats.
Do you like that?
Sure.
It accomplishes two things.
It keeps it light
while letting them know
to expect something big.
WALT:
Uh-huh.
Yeah. No. It's a doozy.
Okay. Anyway, that's where
you will take over,
starting
with your diagnosis.
Pages one and two.
Okay. And it's--
It's gonna run parallel
to the truth,
which makes it easier,
but, um...
Just make sure
to really hit the cancer.
Really touch on
the fear and despair.
It's good to remind them
and to get their sympathy.
We want them to understand why
you'd do something so stupid.
Now, after that, per pages
three and four, after you say:
"Gambling became an addiction,
and I just couldn't control it."
Do you see that?
Yes.
In the middle. Okay.
I put in that line about
robbery, from the GA meeting.
That was good.
So next, I'll chime in about
how it affected our marriage,
starting with the confusion,
the deceit,
why we couldn't
tell anyone--
I'm terribly, terribly ashamed
of my actions.
Yeah.
Two "terribly"s?
It's to show contrition.
I just wouldn't use that word.
I would never say the word
"terribly."
Phrase it however you want.
You're jumping ahead. Now--
And why--?
And why am I so ashamed?
Do I really need
to answer that?
I was, and am,
providing for our family.
Let's just pick up
where we left off.
I'm weak, I'm out of control.
This makes me look like crap.
This has to be
a warts-and-all story.
That's how we'll sell it.
We both look bad.
How do you look bad exactly?
Where is the "I slept
with my boss" bullet point?
I can't seem to find that
anywhere.
For a fired schoolteacher
who cooks crystal meth,
I'd say you're coming out
pretty much ahead.
I don't like it. I don't want
Junior thinking less of me.
At least you won
at gambling.
I'm the bitch mom
who wouldn't cut you slack.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that
I put you through all of this.
How's that sound? Hm?
Here.
Two "sorry"s.
I believe
we were on page five.
So after you say
how very sorry you are,
in your own words,
of course,
we're almost to the end.
And then I say
how proud I am of you
for joining
a 12-step program.
And this is where
I think we should enact
how we're feeling,
you know?
Just a suggestion.
You might look down at the floor
with remorse. Hm?
What?
You don't have to mean it.
You just stare down
at your feet, Walt, okay?
Then I'm gonna...
I was thinking
of taking Marie's hand
and saying something
emotional like:
It's such a relief
to tell you.
We're glad we have
a strong family to help us.
That we can all
support each other.
And then maybe
I'll tear up a little.
I don't know.
We'll see what happens
in the moment.
You're gonna cry on cue?
I said, I don't know.
Maybe.
When you dab your eyes,
with your right hand or left?
One tear? Two tears? How many?
This has to be convincing.
Especially to Hank. I'm doing
the best I can here, Walt.
And yes, I'm thorough.
Maybe lying doesn't come
as easily to me as you.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hey.
Guys! Come on in! Hi!
Good to see you!
Hey.
HANK: You little punk! Hey.
Great to see you.
How you doing?
Look at my little princess.
She's getting big.
Yeah. And heavy too.
Is that food I'm smelling?
I might get
an honest-to-God meal here?
You look good.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Your Aunt Marie, she's cute,
but she could burn water.
You are so hilarious. Show
the boys your rock collection.
We're gonna get organized.
It'll be 20 minutes.
You have a rock collection?
It's a mineral collection.
Just something I've--
You wanna see it?
Sure.
All right. Let's go see it.
Oh, hey, let me--
Hey, no. I-- I got it.
Come on, guys.
It's down the hall here.
HANK:
That one, that's rhodonite.
It's manganese inosilicate.
WALT JR.:
Cool. What makes it be
all pink like that?
That's the manganese part.
It oxidizes, like rust.
WALT:
Manganese can have
an oxidation state
of between minus-three
and plus-seven,
which takes it through a range
of colors. Purple, green, blue.
Its most stable state
is plus-two, which is pale pink.
So...
Exactly.
Whatever the hell he said.
Anyway, you get the idea.
WALT:
Yeah, it's interesting.
Interesting stuff, that.
Really.
Oh, hey. Yeah, give me that.
Give me that file, will you?
Check this out.
I've been working on
something here.
I'm doing
a little consulting.
You know, weighing in
on a case for A.P.D.
Put that in for me.
Put that in over there.
Hank, what is this?
It's not a dead body?
Oh, no, no, no.
Nothing like that. No.
Seriously, you guys
you gotta check this out.
This is good. Ready?
Let me get it going here.
[NEW WAVE MUSIC
PLAYING ON TV]
[LAUGHS]
Look at this guy.
Look at--
♪ Machine is waiting
All systems are go ♪
♪ Are you sure
Control is not convinced ♪
♪ But the computer
Has the evidence ♪
♪ No need to abort ♪
♪ The countdown starts ♪
HANK:
Oh, man. You can't
make this stuff up.
♪ Four, three, two, one ♪
♪ Earth below us ♪
WALT JR.:
Who is this?
HANK:
That, my friends,
is Albuquerque's
public enemy number one.
♪ Calling, calling ♪
♪ Home ♪
SKYLER:
It's such a relief
to finally tell you.
We're just so glad
we have a strong family
to help us through this.
That we can all
support each other.
Jesus. I don't even know
where to-- Holy shit.
Ah. Yeah.
Walter H. White.
Man of hidden talents.
Dad, you're such a stud.
How much did you win exactly?
Dad?
I don't think
I have exact figures.
It's enough to-- After taxes,
of course, to buy the car wash.
Maybe even pay for
a couple of halfway reasonable
college educations.
Damn, Dad, why'd you quit?
I can totally get a car
for my birthday now, right?
Son, I'm terribly, terribly
ashamed of my actions.
Would you excuse me, please?
I need to use the restroom.
Wow.
[♪♪♪]
HANK:
Walt?
Hey! Whoa.
Oh, sorry.
Thought you might have
fallen in.
No, no, I just...
Hey, man, that was
some big stuff back there.
No, we wanted
to be thorough, so...
Yeah, well,
it was quite a tale.
Couldn't have been easy
to, you know, talk about.
You know, Walt, if you...
You can always
bend my ear, right?
I mean,
if you ever need to talk
or just blow off some steam,
I'm here.
Not going anywhere, so...
Thanks, Hank.
Same goes for me,
you know.
If you ever wanna
bounce anything off me,
I don't know, casework,
anything, really.
Sometimes just talking
something through,
you know, really can
make a difference.
HANK:
We're not talking
bathtub crank here.
This is
a big-ass operation.
You know, hundreds of pounds
a week. Maybe more.
So who is this person?
What do you know about him?
Other than he's deader
than a Texas salad bar
and has
a decent set of pipes?
I'd say he's my guy.
Your guy?
There's this mystery man
I've been chasing
for the better part
of a year.
Cooks the purest meth that
me or anyone else has ever seen.
Goes by the name
of Heisenberg.
Hm.
Yeah. Pretty weird, huh?
I looked him up.
It was one of Hitler's guys.
A physicist named
Werner Heisenberg.
Real cute, huh?
With a handle like that,
guy's gotta be some sort of...
Some sort of an egghead.
No offense. Heh, heh.
And here we go.
Gale "Major Tom" Boetticher.
Anyway, I just wanna see
if I'm, you know,
not barking up the wrong tree,
chemically speaking.
As far as I can make out,
he's writing about
a phenylacetone cook, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. Pretty rare these days,
but it does jibe with the blue
stuff I've been tracking.
"Two sticks
dairy-free soy margarine,
two-third cup turbinado sugar."
[HANK LAUGHS]
It's a recipe
for vegan s'mores.
There's all kinds of crazy crap
in there.
Yeah, like, you know,
top-ten recumbent bicycles,
indoor composting tips.
All right next to the mother
of methamphetamine syntheses.
This guy was a...
Man, he was a real character.
Yeah, he seems unique.
Yeah. Let me show you something.
Give it here.
Right here at the...
Right here at the top it says:
"To W.W.
My star, my perfect silence."
W.W. Heh, heh, heh.
I mean, who do you figure
that is?
Woodrow Wilson?
Willy Wonka?
Walter White?
Heh.
You got me.
W.W. Hm.
Wait a minute.
Let me see this...
for a second,
because I think I remembered...
Ah. Here.
Yes.
Yeah.
"When I Heard
the Learn'd Astronomer."
Learned.
And from time to time
Look'd up in perfect silence
At the stars.
It's a poem by Walt Whitman.
Your W.W.
You freaking brainiac.
[HANK LAUGHS]
I must have skipped that day
in school or something.
I been chasing my tail about
that one. Bet you're right.
Well, I'm glad I could help.
Yeah.
Walt Whitman.
Huh.
So you think this Gale person
is your Heisenberg?
Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
God, I wanted to get this guy.
It looks like you did.
No, I mean, you know,
me personally, you know?
I wanted to be the one
to slap the handcuffs on him,
that kind of shit.
Popeye Doyle
waving to Frog One.
If I recall, at least from
the first French Connection,
Popeye Doyle
never actually caught him.
Heh.
Yeah, I guess me
and old Popeye, huh?
Day late and a dollar short.
What about the person
who killed him?
A.P.D.'s problem, not mine.
Any leads?
My buddy Tim says
they got some fingerprints
they're trying to ID.
Eyewitness saw a person
of interest. Might get lucky.
Somebody knows. They'll track
the shooter eventually.
[El-P'S "FLYENTOLOGY"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Jesse.
[GRUNTS]
♪ Freak flash, admission
Of the faithfully shaken ♪
♪ Now trapped
30 thousand and droppin' ♪
♪ It's on and poppin'
At last ♪
♪ Keep me in the sky
That's all that I cry ♪
♪ I'll become your servant
If it's worth your time ♪
♪ Keep me in the sky
That's all that I'll say ♪
♪ I'll become your soldier
At least for this day ♪
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[CLIPPERS WHIRRING]
♪ There is no intellect
In the air ♪
Jesse.
JESSE:
What's up?
♪ Just a working example
Of faith versus physics ♪
♪ Flyentology ♪
♪ Everybody
Get your ticket today ♪
WALT:
I need to talk to you.
Okay.
♪ Flyentology
Fly, flyentology ♪
Now.
Go ahead.
Would you stop doing
what you're doing, please?
I'm not done, yo.
And that dude's next.
[WHIRRING STOPS]
What the hell? What is wrong--?
We have business to discuss.
So discuss. Jesus.
Let go of me.
Gale's murder
is being investigated.
Uh, duh.
I have it on good authority
they found fingerprints.
Not mine.
We done here?
No, we are not done here.
What if they are yours?
How can you be so sure?
Because I'm here.
Your brother-in-law's
got a hard-on for me,
if the cops found fingerprints--
Shh.
If the cops found my prints
within five blocks,
they would've
picked me up by now.
What about the casing?
Oh, my God.
Or casings?
How many times
did you shoot him, anyway?
Jesse, did you
pick up the casings?
Did you pick them up?
No.
Yeah, well...
Listen, we gotta go over this
step-by-step, everything.
Tell me exactly what happened
from the moment you got there.
I got in, I got out.
No.
No, I need to know specifics.
We'll start from the beginning.
You drove over there.
You went to his door, right?
Jesse, I need you
to concentrate.
This is very important.
Did you knock or ring?
Knock or ring?
Knock.
Good, good. That's very good.
Now listen.
Assume Gale answered the door.
What happened after that?
Did he recognize you?
Did you say anything
to each other?
Did you walk into the room or
did you shoot him right there?
What?
Who wants to make 100 bucks?
Yeah.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
SAUL:
Look, the kid's probably right.
If they had anything on him,
he'd be locked up already.
What about my brother-in-law?
He suspects Jess--
He knows Jesse is involved
in the sale of blue meth.
That was Hank's
one-and-only lead.
What if he puts
two and two together,
and he goes after Jesse
for the murder?
Goes after him how,
on his Rascal scooter?
Ahem. That perhaps
sounded insensitive.
But if he goes after him,
I'll sue his ass
for police brutality,
harassment, assault
and 16 other things.
No, history those two
have together, being what it is,
gotta figure your
brother-in-law's smart enough
not to go down that road.
Goose egg. Bubkes.
That's what the cops got.
I wouldn't worry about it.
Yeah, what else should I
not worry about, Saul?
Should I not worry Gus plans
to murder me at first chance?
That my drug-addicted partner
doesn't seem to care
whether he lives or dies?
You should see his house.
It's like skid row.
He has actual hobos
living there.
Now, how long before Gus decides
he's too big of a risk?
Jeez, I got Mike,
that grunting, dead-eyed cretin
sucker-punching me in the face.
I've got Gus
wielding a box cutter.
I mean, Western Union,
message received.
Let me ask you. When did this
stop being a business?
Why am I the only person
capable of behaving
in a professional manner?
[MUTTERS]
Any way you slice it,
everyone is in danger.
I mean, how can I
protect anyone?
My family, Jesse, myself?
My name never comes up
with those guys, does it?
And meanwhile, we're buying
this stupid car wash.
Oh, yeah. That ship
has sailed, bon voyage.
We are committed. We already
told our family about it.
And now Skyler,
I'm sure she believes--
She needs to believe that
everything is neat and tidy.
And she's telling herself
I work in this quiet little lab
with a white lab coat
and a pocket protector,
and when my contract is up,
I'll just hang it all up,
tip my hat and walk away.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, God.
How did everything
get so screwed up?
Yeah, you do have a little
shit-creek action happening.
You know, FYI,
you can buy a paddle.
This is a last-resort,
back-pocket kind of thing,
but if you really gotta
protect yourself, disappear...
Poof.
There's a guy
who can make it happen.
They call him a "disappearer."
For a substantial fee,
and I do mean substantial,
you and your loved ones
can vanish. Untraceable.
I mean, he sets you up
with a whole new life.
What, like a witness protection
kind of thing?
Beyond.
I mean, off the grid.
New identities,
new everything.
No one would ever
be able to trace you.
Be clear. This is an end game,
if you get my meaning.
I mean,
there's no coming back.
[SIGHS]
So you want his card?
God, there's gotta be
something else that I can do.
Some way to keep everything
from spiraling out of control.
From what you told me,
it sounds like Pinkman
is first up in
the imminent-demise department.
Gus won't risk
letting the police find Jesse.
I know him. He won't.
MAN:
I'm not kidding. If you think
about it, you can't even see it.
How can you know how bad
radio frequencies, microwaves
and cell phones
are getting you?
You could be strolling through
security at the airport--
Hey, wake up, bitches.
MAN:
You get waved through
a full-body x-ray scanner.
Next day, you could be
dead or dying
from all the radiation
they say is safe.
But there's no way. It has
to deliver a concentrated dose.
Enough to penetrate clothes.
The accumulated amount
could be dangerous
to susceptible individuals,
especially from a rural area.
Yo.
The ozone layer is already thin
because of the cow farts.
Yo!
Oh, hey.
Make sure there's pizza here
when I get back.
All right? Enough for everybody.
Oh, yeah.
I can do that.
I can definitely do that.
Not a problem. I can get
the stuff, the pizza and stuff.
But as far as the financial
situation, you know...
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
Just hang on. Hang on.
Yeah, yeah.
And you know,
the concentrated doses,
it's gonna fuck
with your bone marrow,
and it's gonna mess up...
Because-- Because especially
if you have cancer.
You know, because if you gotta
get a bone-marrow transplant,
your odds are 60 percent.
You got a 60 percent chan--
Hey.
MAN:
Oh.
JESSE:
Hey, hey.
Get some dipping sticks too, yo.
Yeah, I can definitely get
dipping sticks.
All right. I can get them.
[BOTTLES CLATTER]
[GRUNTS]
[CAMERA WHIRRING]
[DANCE MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ 808, ooh, 808 ♪
♪ 808, kick drum
Kick drum ♪
♪ 808, snare drum
Snare drum, clap ♪
♪ Got an 808 this and a this
And a that ♪
♪ Got an 808 boom
And an 808 bat ♪
[CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY]
Hey, smoke it up, bitches.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
♪ 808 ♪
[DRAWER CLOSES]
[VIDEO GAME BEGINS]
MAN:
Gotcha!
[SIGHS]
MIKE:
Wake up.
What's up?
What's up with your ear?
Downstairs. Now.
Where is everybody?
I invited your guests
to leave.
Know who this is?
Nope.
You ought to.
He's been at your house
for three solid days.
Okay.
He stole your money.
That $78,000 or so
look familiar?
This is it?
That's it.
[COUGHS]
JESSE:
Okay. Thanks.
Wanna know what's next for
Little Miss Pissed-in-His-Pants?
No.
You sure, now?
Yep.
Don't wanna take a wild guess?
You're gonna kill him.
Is this the part where
I beg you not to do it?
Oh, please, please.
And then what?
I'm supposed to promise,
cross my heart,
to straighten up and fly right
or toe the line
or some other crap
that I'm not gonna say?
Is that what your little show
here was all about?
You're on thin ice,
you little shithead.
You know that?
[LAUGHS]
You ain't gonna smoke
that dude in there.
You know how come I know?
You went through the trouble
of putting a blindfold on him.
I'm going back to bed.
Let yourselves out.
[DOOR OPENS]
GUS:
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
How's the ear?
Mending.
What can I do for you?
It's Pinkman.
He's become
increasingly incautious.
He's a risk.
A liability.
I know he and Walter
come as a team
and that Walter
won't like it,
but something's
gotta be done.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[MACHINERY WHIRRING]
You gotta be kidding.
JESSE [ON ANSWERING MACHINE]:
Hey, it's me.
Wait for the thing.
Right.
This is message number three.
You'd better be ready
in two minutes,
because I am right outside
your door.
[♪♪♪]
Jesse.
Jesse!
Damn it.
JESSE:
Hey, it's me.
Wait for the thing.
Oh, great.
Jesse!
This is perfect.
You are a piece of work,
you know that?
[GRUNTS]
Jesse?
Jesse.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATING]
JESSE:
Hey, it's me.
Wait for the thing.
[TONE BEEPS]
[♪♪♪]
[CAMERA WHIRRING]
Where is he?
Gonna ask where we're going?
Nope.
[♪♪♪]