[TIRES SCREECHING]
WALT:
Say you understand.
You understand?
[CAR HORN HONKING]
Tell me you understand, Saul!
[HORN HONKING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
Every dollar.
If you don't hear from me
in 24 hours--
No, look. Shut-- Saul.
Saul, shut up.
Shut up and listen to me.
I want you to give her every
last dollar, do you hear me?
I don't care if you stuff it
in trash bags.
Just make sure
she gets everything.
All right?
Just make it happen.
Ah!
[TIRES SCREECH]
[HORN HONKING]
SKYLER:
Hi. You've reached
the White family.
Please leave a message.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Uh...
Hey. It's me.
Um...
I-- I...
I just wanted to say
that I was thinking
about you
and the kids, and...
I love you.
[TIRES SCREECH]
[CAR HORNS HONK]
[♪♪♪]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[DOOR BELL DINGING]
Hello, would you
like to try
our breakfast chicken
chalupa combo meal?
Gus Fring.
Excuse me?
Gustavo Fring,
your boss.
Now, please.
Mr. Fring isn't here right now.
Is there some--?
He's here. His car is parked
out front. He's here.
He was here.
Mr. Fring was--
You just go in the back and you
tell him it's Walter White.
Understand?
He'll know what it's about.
I'll wait.
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE]
[DISHES CLATTERING]
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
[DOOR BELL DINGLES]
[CELL PHONE VIBRATING]
MAN:
Yeah, let me get
a chalupa special.
Hello?
MIKE [OVER PHONE]:
Walter, what exactly
are you doing?
Where's Jesse?
Jesse's with me.
He's fine.
What, do you expect me
to just believe that?
I'm crossing
my heart, Walter.
Where is he?
Hold on.
JESSE:
Yo.
Jesse?
Yeah. What's up?
Jesse, w-w-where are you?
With Mike.
[WHISPERING]
I know you're with Mike.
Are-- Are you all right?
Does he have a gun on you?
No.
What's going on, then?
We're driving.
Driving.
Driving where?
I don't know.
Um, north?
[SIGHS]
Why is he driving you?
Where is he going?
Beats me.
I-- I don't--
Put Mike back on.
Hello again.
Mike, tell me now
exactly what is going on.
Jesse's with me today.
So, what you need to do
is to go back to your lab
and get on with the cook.
You're gonna have to muddle
through this one without him.
That's what's going on.
But it doesn't--
Goodbye, Walter.
Mike--
[♪♪♪]
Sir.
Excuse me. Hey.
You're not allowed back there.
Excuse me, sir.
As I said, sir,
Mr. Fring is not here.
This area is for
employees only,
and I have to ask
that you leave immediately.
What you told Mr. White,
that's...
It's just bullshit, right?
What, you, uh, figure on just
leaving me in some ditch?
What do you care?
I don't.
But I'll tell you now,
you better shoot straight,
old man,
or I'll slice off your other ear
before this is over.
[TRUNK CREAKING CLOSED]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SIGHS]
You coming?
We gotta do this
six more times today
with a lot of miles
in between.
I'd like to finish
before dark.
[CAR DOOR CREAKING CLOSED]
[ENGINE STARTING]
HANK:
This freaking guy,
I tell you what.
It's like Scarface had sex
with Mr. Rogers or something.
[LAUGHS]
Who does this,
you know?
Your boy Heisenberg,
thought we had him already.
Yeah. Keep dreaming.
Yeah, no. Getz busted him
a few months back.
Yeah, well, no offense
to Detective
Doogie Howser there,
but all he caught
was a dipshit lifer
by the name
of Jimmy In-'N-Out.
This one,
he's your Heisenberg?
Yeah, I believe he is.
So, what are you thinking?
Rival drug gang taking out
the mastermind?
Any names
I should check out?
I wish I could
help you there.
Only two people I know
connected with the blue stuff.
One is a beanie-wearing
jizz stain
by the name of Brandon Mayhew,
street name "Badger."
Definitely not a player.
And the other one
is Jesse Pinkman.
He and I have a history.
Yeah.
You see Pinkman
as a shooter?
That would surprise me.
Well, we have a composite
of a person of interest.
It's a guy the neighbors saw
at Boetticher's place
right after the shooting.
Yeah. Sorry.
No, hang on to it,
just in case.
We got a couple of prints
we're hoping to ID.
If I get any kind of hit,
I'll keep you in the loop
on that.
You know, um, Tim,
look, I appreciate
what you're doing, really.
You know, keeping me
involved and all.
But, you know,
finding this guy
Heisenberg dead like this...
I have to say, it...
kind of feels
like closure to me, you know?
Hank, you really are
a big help here.
No, I know.
I-- I get it, really.
But I'm done.
[COUGHS]
[SIGHS]
You don't need to do that.
This is why
I'm out here, right?
To be, like,
your backup?
Uh-huh.
So if I'm out here
in a guard-type capacity
to watch over the money,
that means I need,
like, a gun, right?
Nope.
[SIGHS]
I mean, isn't that, like,
completely idiotic
for me to be out here
without a gun?
You haven't said dick
about what I'm supposed
to be doing.
Now I'm supposed to do it
without a gun?
How does that
even make sense?
What? I can smoke, right?
Not a chance.
[ENGINE STARTING]
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[MAN SINGING IN SPANISH]
[WOMAN SINGING IN SPANISH]
[SIGHS]
[SPUTTERING]
[ROCK MUSIC BLARING
OVER RADIO]
[ROCK MUSIC TURNED OFF]
♪ Fallacies, fallacies ♪
♪ One for you
And two for me ♪
[YAWNING]
[SIGHS]
It's finally hitting me
what the plan is here.
It's to bore me to death.
So mission accomplished,
because it's totally
working.
Great job.
You know, I really do get
what's going on
with all the dead drops
and bags of cash.
Me and my boys had
the exact same system
when I was running things.
My crew.
Nowhere near the same cheese
you guys are slinging,
but same theory.
You know, maintain separation
between dealer and supplier,
reduce risk,
et cetera.
Look, don't you think
it'd be good
if there was some back-and-forth
communication here?
You got me riding shotgun
to every dark anal recess
in the state.
Be nice if you
clued me in a little.
I mean, I'm here
to do a job, right?
And, I mean, yo, like,
if I'm the guy,
then you should just tell me
what the hell is up.
What?
You are not the guy.
You're not capable
of being the guy.
I had a guy,
but now I don't.
You are not the guy.
Then what the hell
am I doing here?
I don't know.
It's not my call.
I just do
what I'm told.
And now you're gonna do
what you're told,
which is to sit here,
shut up,
and stay in the car till we
finish our pickups. You got it?
[♪♪♪]
[WOMAN SINGING IN SPANISH]
[GRUNTING]
[SIGHS]
[MACHINE BEEPING]
[PANTING]
[WHIRRING]
[SIGHS]
[WATCH BEEPING]
Oh!
We having
second thoughts?
Every hour of every day.
[ALAN CHUCKLES]
Let me tell you,
that is perfectly normal.
But your expectations
are realistic.
You have a good,
solid business plan.
I'm feeling
very confident.
You have an excellent shot
at making this work.
[SIGHS]
Walt?
Hm?
SKYLER: Are you good?
Yeah.
[EXHALES]
All right.
Well, my congratulations
to the both of you.
Thank you
very much, Alan.
It is my pleasure.
Mr. White.
Best of luck.
Thank you.
I'm bringing
the car over
first thing next week
for a wash and wax.
Oh,
we'll be looking for you.
ALAN: I'll be there.
[SKYLER LAUGHS]
Thank you again.
ALAN: You're welcome.
Bye-bye.
ALAN: Bye-bye.
Wow.
It's official.
How are you feeling?
I'm...
Well, I'm--
How do you feel?
Um...
Nervous.
Scared.
This is a big step,
Walt.
If we don't
do this right--
We'll be fine.
We will?
Tell me again.
We will be fine.
Believe it.
If we're gonna do this,
I mean, really gonna do this,
then we have
to promise each other
no more secrets.
There can't be any mistakes
like before.
There has to be
complete honesty.
I'm all for that.
Good.
Well, then, um,
how about a drink
to celebrate?
Well--
Well, we own
a big-ass car wash now.
We do. I guess that merits
a celebration.
Nothing too expensive.
Right. Right.
Non-fancy liquor it is.
Yes.
Just as long
as it gets the job done.
Oh.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
WALT [OVER ANSWERING MACHINE]:
Uh, i-it's me.
I just wanted to say that I was
thinking about you and--
And the kids, and, uh...
I love you.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
[MOANING]
[BOTH PANTING]
Okay.
Just take it off.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
[SKYLER MOANING]
[SIGHS]
The sheets, they smell different
than I remember.
Hm?
Don't they?
Oh.
New fabric softener.
Yeah, I like it.
I, uh, also got a new haircut.
I don't know if you--
Oh, yes, I-- I was gonna
say something.
Were you, really?
[LAUGHS]
I do like it.
Thanks.
So, um,
dinner tomorrow night?
I told Marie that we'd come over
and eat with them.
Think maybe
you'll be free?
Yeah.
Yeah, we can do that.
That'll-- That'll be nice.
Good.
Marie says it's about
the only thing
that'll get Hank
out of his room.
WALT, JR.:
Mom?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Ooh.
Hey, Mom? Dad?
WALT:
Hey, son.
Where are you?
WALT:
Uh, we're-- We're back here.
We'll be out in a minute.
Oh, God.
[WHISPERING]
Seriously?
I'm parked
in the driveway.
Oh, this is going to make
for some very interesting
dinner conversation.
He is definitely gonna ask
about our living situation now.
Maybe, um...
Maybe you should
move back in.
You know, just so it's, uh,
easier to explain to everyone.
You think?
[WATCH BEEPING]
I have to get back
to work.
You know, schedule.
Yeah.
[FORKLIFT WHIRRING]
[FORKLIFT BEEPING]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Damn it.
Hey!
Hey! This is a two-man job.
I can't do it alone.
I'm done. That's it.
Finished. Nothing else happens
until I get my partner back.
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
[FOOTSTEPS]
Jesse?
Where's Jesse?
I need him.
You people
have me down here
trying to complete
a two-man operation by myself!
It's unacceptable.
It's dangerous
and counterproductive.
Jesse operates the forklift,
not me.
That's just one of the many,
many things he does
around the lab
that keeps us on schedule,
so I suggest
that you get him back down here
as soon as you--
Are you listening to me?
Hello?
[FORKLIFT WHIRRING]
[FORKLIFT BEEPING]
Where do you want it?
This is it, right?
Last stop?
Hey, I've been counting, yo.
No more pickups after--
[DOOR CLOSES]
♪ Fallacies, fallacies ♪
[YAWNS]
♪ One for you
And two for me ♪
♪ Fallacies... ♪
[♪♪♪]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[SIGHS]
[MEN SINGING IN SPANISH
OVER RADIO]
Yeah. I'm gonna need
to be picked up. Now.
Garcia's on Central.
Honk once.
I'll meet you
in the parking lot.
Cancel that.
Hey, this dude--
This dude was coming
right at me with a--
With a shotgun.
They, like,
blocked the alley
and they were gonna rip us off.
I didn't have a choice, okay?
I had to put it
in reverse,
slam into the guy's car,
and just--
[SIGHS]
I saw.
You saw.
Oh, Jesus.
I just--
I don't know.
Go ahead, kid.
Smoke up.
[CAR SQUEALING]
[SIGHING]
Morning.
Hey. Good morning, son.
You want me
to pour you some juice?
I'll take a coffee.
Didn't know
you started drinking coffee.
Yeah. I also started
tying my own shoelaces too,
all by myself.
[CHUCKLING]
Go grab a mug.
Milk? Sugar?
Just black.
Black. I like it.
Hey, Dad, I, uh--
I just gotta say...
I-- I just wanted to say
it's really cool
to have you here.
Thank you, son.
It's cool
to be back home.
It just feels...
Mom said you're moving back in
this Tuesday.
She...?
She said that?
Yeah.
Tuesday, is it?
Huh.
How about that?
[POUNDING]
Jesse. Jesse.
Yo, what's up?
What are you doing?
Um, breaking ice.
No, I mean, what are you--?
What are you doing here?
Where's your car?
Mike dropped me off.
Jesse.
Jesse!
What happened yesterday?
Where were you?
I was out with Mike,
helped him make pickups.
Picking up what?
Cash. Dead drops.
Mike made the pickups
and I guarded him.
You...
guarded Mike?
What is this,
some kind of a joke?
Hey, know what? Two dudes tried
to rob us and I saved the stash.
I took care of business,
just like I'm taking care
of business right now.
You wanna stand there
dicking around,
or you wanna suit up
and get to work?
Get in gear, yo,
if you wanna do this,
because I'm meeting up
with Mike this afternoon.
What, again? Why?
Guess I have two jobs now.
[INDUSTRIAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES]
[POUNDING RESUMES]
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
Los Pollos Hermanos,
can I take your order?
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Any injuries?
Twisted ankle,
nothing too bad.
It all went like you thought
it would, more or less.
I will, of course, reimburse you
for the damage to your vehicles.
Hm.
Questions?
Uh-huh.
More than a few, yeah.
But I know better
than to ask.
Anyway,
just like you wanted.
The kid's a hero.
[CAR DOOR CLOSING]
SKYLER:
Just the idea of owning
a car wash seems so daunting,
but I have to remind...
Who is the most
beautiful little girl
in the world?
I think it's you.
So coming into a business
like this,
that's up and running
and fully operational,
puts us way ahead
of the game.
You know, we're gonna still
have some changeover time,
and we'll have to hire
some people.
But we do have a staff in place,
so, you know,
luckily we'll be able to hold on
to most of Bogdan's employees.
We might lose a few to the
UltraWash across town, though.
[LAUGHS]
They're making a grab,
I hear.
You gonna put the kid to work?
I've got school.
I'm not talking about you.
Talking about your sister.
I wouldn't let you near my car.
Ha, ha.
Hey, that's not a bad idea,
you guys.
You should put Holly
on the sign.
Like a mascot?
Like the Gerber baby.
I would get my car washed there
every day
if I saw her face
out front.
What about me?
The goal is to bring customers
in, not scare them away, so...
Walt, there's another bottle
in the kitchen.
Just help yourself.
Ah. Good.
WALT, JR.:
Um, maybe we could roll
Uncle Hank through the car wash.
He could be
the first customer.
[MARIE LAUGHS]
WALT JR.:
The wipe-down crew
would clean you up good.
[ALL LAUGH]
HANK:
I got your wipe-down right here.
MARIE:
Hank, can we just maybe
get through one meal
without you grabbing
your crotch?
So, what are you gonna do
with Holly all day?
You can't take her to work
with all those chemicals
and migrants hanging around.
SKYLER: Marie...
MARIE: What? That can't be safe.
SKYLER:
Fortunately, five minutes
from the car wash,
there is the top child-care
center in the city.
The National Child Care
Association
gives it really high ratings.
So that's a huge relief and,
you know,
we could walk there
if we had to.
HANK:
Sky, I gotta tell you,
I'm just--
I'm really,
really impressed.
You came together on this.
I'm really happy that
it's working out for you.
SKYLER:
It's been a little scary,
but it needed to be done.
And we get possession
of the keys tomorrow.
MARIE:
Oh, that's awesome.
WALT JR.:
I-- I-- I can't wait to see
what kind of car I'm going
to get for my birthday,
now with all this money
rolling in.
SKYLER:
I think you've been spending
too much time around Hank.
WALT JR.:
The squeaky wheel gets
the grease. Right, Uncle Hank?
HANK:
Squeaky and greasy.
That's you, my friend.
[SKYLER LAUGHS]
HANK:
Hey, Nick the Greek,
you gonna share that bottle
or what?
Oh. Yeah. Sorry.
WALT JR.:
Who's Nick the Greek?
He's a famous big-time
card player.
Hank, that's not funny.
What? It's a compliment.
Well, that's even worse, then.
You're giving
positive reinforcement
to behavior that Walt is working
very, very hard to change.
Right, Skyler?
Yeah.
I don't see how it's bad.
Dad's raking in
the beaucoup bucks now.
You know, I just think maybe
we could change the subject?
Yeah. Sure. You know.
Absolutely.
Hey, Uncle Hank, what about
that case you were looking at
with that crazy singing guy?
Ah, I'm off that.
I-- I gave my assessment
to A.P.D. I'm done.
The case of the crazy
singing guy.
Hm, sounds like
an Encyclopedia Brown story.
Crazy is--
Is the wrong word.
This guy, Gale Boetticher,
he was-- He was eccentric.
A real character, you know?
He's-- He's dead now.
SKYLER:
Who was he?
WALT JR.:
He was a meth cook.
HANK:
Uh, he was a meth chef.
I mean, we're talking
five stars.
Candles and white
tablecloth.
Hey, I can't believe these words
are gonna come out of my mouth,
but he was a genius,
plain and simple.
I mean, boy, if he had applied
that big brain of his
to something good,
I don't know, who knows,
he could've helped humanity
or something like that.
I mean, how many actual geniuses
are there in the world, right?
If he'd kind of taken his life
in a different direction,
who knows?
Hank...
not to tell you your business,
but I'm not sure I agree.
What do you mean?
Well, I mean,
you showed me that notebook,
and from what I saw--
And this is just
my humble opinion.
From what I saw
on those papers...
Genius?
Not so much.
I mean, there was no reasoning,
no deductions in those pages.
So to my eye,
all his brilliance
looks like nothing more
than just simple rote copying.
Probably of someone
else's work.
Believe me, I have been around
enough students to know.
This genius of yours...
maybe he's still
out there.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Hank.
Oh, hey, babe.
Uh, Tim stopped by.
He-- He brought over
some file boxes on that case.
Thought I'd take
another peek.
That's great.
Sorry about the mess.
No, no, no. Don't be.
You want me
to make some coffee?
Yeah.
Yeah, that'd be good.
Hm.
You find something?
Oh, just this guy
I'm looking at.
You know, everything he--
He buys and eats
is organic,
fair trade, vegan.
Since when do vegans
eat fried chicken?
[♪♪♪]