[MAN EXHALING]
[TRUCK RATTLING]
[TRUCK ACCELERATES]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[AIR BRAKES HISS]
[DOOR OPENS]
MAN:
No, no, no!
[GUNSHOT]
[DOOR OPENS]
[POWER TOOL WHIRRING]
[METAL CLANKS]
[ENGINE IDLING]
[♪♪♪]
[METAL CLANKS]
[ENGINE ACCELERATES]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[MEN POUNDING
INSIDE TRUCK]
Hey.
[BOTH COUGHING]
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
[BOTH COUGHING AND GRUNTING]
[COUGHING AND GRUNTING
CONTINUE]
[♪♪♪]
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
WALT:
Uh, it's me.
I wanted to say I was thinking
about you and the kids.
I love you.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Uh, it's me.
I wanted to say I was thinking
about you and the kids, and--
[SNORING LIGHTLY]
WALT:
Morning.
Afternoon.
Oh, really?
Jesus.
You shouldn't have
let me sleep.
You needed it.
[SIGHS]
Heh.
Skyler,
I don't entirely remember
what happened last night.
I mean, I might have said
some things that--
Did you know
this Gale Boetticher person?
Skyler,
I can't even focus on--
Gale Boetticher.
Did you know him?
My God. What--?
What exactly did I say
last night?
Just enough.
Did you work together?
[SIGHS]
Who killed him?
Was it the people you work for?
Definitely not.
Was it somebody who...
at some point, might want
to do the same to you?
I seriously doubt it.
No.
Oh, God.
SKYLER:
I think I know
what happened last night.
WALT:
Mm. I know exactly
what happened last night.
I drank too much wine.
SKYLER:
You told Hank
that the man he was looking for
might still be out there.
That it might not be
this Boetticher after all.
And I was up all night,
wondering why
you would say that to him.
WALT:
Mm. Because I was drunk, Skyler.
SKYLER:
No, but then I was
remembering your black eye.
Your business disagreement that
you don't want to talk about.
Look, I don't want to talk
about any of this. Ever.
The firewall, all right?
Church and state.
That's how we need to approach
this thing.
Then I remembered the message
you left me the other day,
when you said you loved me.
When I heard that,
I thought that maybe you--
I don't know,
that you were regretting
what's happened between us.
And I get that.
After last night, I...
Walt, I think you're scared.
I think that message
was some kind of goodbye.
No, Skyler.
I think last night
was a cry for help.
Oh, Jesus.
A cry for help?
I think some part of you
wants Hank to catch you.
Wow.
That is just...
That is--
That is it exactly. Yes.
You're like
Dr. Joyce Brothers here.
God.
At least
this would all be over.
There's a tremendous weight
just lifted off of me.
Now I understand myself.
Thank you. Thank you.
Walt, I've said it before.
If you are in danger,
we go to the police.
I don't want to hear
about the police.
I do not say that lightly.
I know what it could do
to this family.
But if it's the only
real choice we have,
if it's either that
or you getting shot--
I don't want to hear
about the police.
You're not
some hardened criminal, Walt.
You are in over your head.
That's what we tell them,
that's the truth.
That is not the truth.
Of course it is.
A schoolteacher, cancer,
desperate for money...
We're done here.
Roped into-- Unable to quit.
You told me that
yourself, Walt.
Jesus, what was I thinking?
Walt, please.
Let's both of us stop trying
to justify this whole thing
and admit
you're in danger.
Who are you talking to
right now?
Who is it you think you see?
Do you know
how much I make a year?
I mean, even if I told you,
you wouldn't believe it.
You know what would happen if
I decided to stop going to work?
A business big enough
that it could be listed
on the NASDAQ goes belly up.
Disappears. It ceases to exist
without me. No.
You clearly don't know
who you're talking to,
so let me clue you in.
I am not in danger, Skyler.
I am the danger.
A guy opens his door
and gets shot,
and you think that of me? No.
I am the one who knocks.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[GROANS]
WALT:
Look, I was...
Skyler?
Here we are.
Just like you left it.
And where is
your pretty wife?
She has other business
to attend to.
Well, like I say to her,
place sells as is.
Understand?
Yes, I understand.
Good, good.
I don't want her coming back
with more demands.
She gave me hard time
when we settled on price.
We're all on the same page,
Bogdan.
So here is
everything you need.
I keep very good files.
Thank you.
So you are the boss now, huh?
You think you're ready?
Yes, I think so.
Being boss is tough.
I know you think I was hard
on you, but you'll learn.
Being in charge is not easy.
It takes hard work.
You've seen me
work hard, Bogdan.
Yeah?
I don't know.
Not so much, maybe.
But maybe when
you are the boss,
you will just
keep your feet up and relax.
Mm.
The real important thing,
and not everyone knows this,
is to be tough.
Boss has to be tough.
Has to say no to people.
Has to make cashiers
wipe down cars
even if
they don't want to.
Can you be tough,
Walter?
I-- I am sure
you can handle.
And if not, you can always
call your wife, no?
Always sticky.
Yeah.
No problem.
As is.
Who'd have thought
that someday
I would be
handing these keys to you?
Many years. Almost forgot.
WALT:
Bogdan.
As is.
[SIGHS]
[SODA CAN DISPENSES]
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY ON SPEAKERS]
Thank you.
WAITRESS:
Mm-hm.
[SPOON RATTLING]
[SIGHS]
You okay there?
I'm fine.
Just not using is...
Eat something.
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
Yeah?
That's right, both of them.
All right.
I'm on my way.
You need any help?
No.
You want me to call her back?
WALT:
No. No.
What exactly did she say?
I mean, exactly.
Just, you know, she asked
if I was okay and not to worry.
Like that.
Hm. Any rough timetable
on this thing,
as to when
she's coming home?
It's about
the gambling, right?
Well, it's kind of hard to--
Dad, she can't
understand.
It's not like you're doing this
on purpose. You can't help it.
It's not that simple.
Look, you have a disease.
It's like you're an alcoholic,
right?
No, it's not. Not at all.
Yes, it is. I read online.
She's not even allowed
to be mad at you.
She can't be mad at you
about the cancer, can she?
Son, these are two
very different things.
Not really. Gambling addiction
is a sickness.
You can't--
Listen, what is going on with me
is not about some disease.
It's about choices.
Choices that I have made.
Choices I stand by.
WALT JR.:
You're not moving back in,
are you?
WALT:
No.
Hey, you know what?
School can wait.
Why don't we take
a little detour?
What kind of detour?
You'll see.
MAN [OVER P.A.]:
Charlie, pick up line three.
Line three, Charlie.
I think it's time we got you
your own car. What do you think?
What?
I think if
you're going to buy me off,
buy me off.
Get an attendant
over to the lot.
[RAP MUSIC PLAYING INDISTINCTLY
OVER STEREO]
♪ Hic-hiccup
Lay me on the liquor ♪
♪ Came through like a sip cup
I'm pulling like a kicker ♪
Wow.
Amazing. It's amazing.
Yeah. It's good-looking.
That's good.
I'm glad you like it.
I do. Thank you, Dad.
All right. You're welcome.
So you're here.
Yeah.
You're actually here?
To work?
Yeah, man. Jesus.
Jesse.
Come here.
WALT: I need an update.
JESSE: Update on what?
WALT:
An update
on these little field trips
that you've been taking
with Mike.
JESSE:
I told you already.
We pick up money.
Check on things.
Stuff like that.
And you're his bodyguard, right?
What? That's what you said.
I said I guarded him.
Like backup,
like a second set of eyes.
Everybody needs backup,
right?
And this has to be you?
It can't be,
I don't know, Tyrus or any
of the couple dozen muscle-heads
that Gus has working for him?
It has to be Jesse Pinkman.
Why? What, is there something
about you that I don't know?
Are you a former Navy SEAL?
Your hands registered
as lethal weapons?
Register this.
All I'm saying is that
do you not even question this?
Do you really believe you mean
anything to these people?
Not trying to insult. Just
trying to make you see things.
I see they can't
outright kill me,
but they don't want me
getting high.
I see this thing
probably started
as Gus getting Mike
to babysit me.
But you know what?
I saved Mike
from getting robbed,
even killed, maybe.
So maybe I'm not such a loser
after all.
I mean, what if it--? Oh, God.
What if it's all just a setup?
What?
What if this robbery
you stopped wasn't even real?
Think about it. Your first day
out guarding Mike.
He steps out for one second
and what happens?
You immediately get robbed.
You are such an asshole.
Keep your friends close,
your enemies closer.
Like you said, Gus can't
kill you because of me,
he knows I won't stand for it.
He hates the fact
that he needs me.
What does he do?
He goes to work
driving a wedge
between you and me.
If you'd been there,
you'd know it wasn't a setup.
Wait a minute. How long
did those guys chase you, huh?
Because the way you describe it,
they gave up pretty damn easy.
No, no, this whole thing,
all of this,
it's all about me.
[METAL CLATTERS]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Uh, look, just hang on.
Yeah?
I'll be right up.
What?
I got to go.
What? Am I supposed to clean
all this on my own?
Hey.
God--
[BELL RINGS]
[MACHINERY HISSING]
[WOMEN SPEAKING SPANISH]
Ah. Buenos dias, ladies,
buenos dias.
Do you speak English?
No.
No, okay.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Ugh. Help, help.
I need help to clean. Yes.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[ILIA
SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[WOMEN CHATTERING IN SPANISH]
Yes, muy bueno. It's just this--
No.
No, no, no.
[WOMEN SPEAKING SPANISH]
[WALT SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
No, no, ladies.
[VERONICA
SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Let me see, let me see.
I tell you what.
I tell you what. Look, look.
Universal language.
No.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
This one for you. Yeah, sí.
Sí, Presidente Grant.
Very important man.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[WOMEN SPEAKING SPANISH]
Mas dinero after the--
Are we good?
I think we're good.
I think we listened to you.
Please, por favor, por favor.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Ah. Yes.
[WOMEN CHATTERING IN SPANISH]
[♪♪♪]
[COIN CLATTERS]
JESSE:
What's the deal?
Well, the deal is,
we're watching that house.
Couple down on the left
with the tree in the front.
JESSE:
Yeah? What for?
A little birdie told me
there's some guys
that have 3 pounds
of our product they're selling.
And which they sure as hell
didn't get from us.
So, what's the plan?
I just told you.
We sit here
and watch that house
until one of our entrepreneurs
pops his head out.
Then we ask a few questions
and get our property back.
Why don't you just go
break the door down,
pistol-whip those bitches
and show them who's boss?
Because a little birdie
also told me
these guys are into the product
and most likely armed.
Now, what you may not know
about meth-heads--
Or maybe you do.
They're kind of
unpredictable.
I don't care for unpredictable.
So we wait.
Sorry to burst
your bubble, kid,
but that's 90 percent
of the job.
Don't worry.
I brought sandwiches.
[MIKE GROANS]
Yes, sir. Heh.
Uh...
Pimento cheese.
How's that sound?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where you going?
You said they're selling right?
Maybe I'm looking to buy.
[GATE RATTLES]
TUCKER:
Who the hell are you?
MAN: Tucker! Tucker!
I'm here to buy.
MAN: Will you shut the door?
TUCKER: Not my question.
Name's Diesel. Heard you
maybe had some of the blue.
MAN: Shut the door, Tucker!
I just--
Just looking for a teenth, yo.
MAN: Tucker!
Come on, help a brother out.
Will you shut the damn door?
We don't sell to strangers.
MAN: Tucker!
Get off the porch, asshole.
MAN: Will you shut the door?
All right already!
MAN:
Tucker!
[SIGHS]
Guess we'll go
with Plan A, then.
Pop the trunk, would you?
Why?
There's something I need.
And what would that be?
I'm getting those pricks
out of that house.
Oh, your first attempt
being such a wild success?
You may know this whole
PI sit-in-the-car business,
but I know meth-heads.
[GRUNTING]
What are you doing?
Digging.
TUCKER:
Why?
You know why.
How deep are you going?
I don't know.
How deep do you think it is?
Pretty deep.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Hey, you mind taking over
for a minute?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, mind if I use your john?
Yeah.
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
Tucker.
Tucker!
Who the hell are you?
I just--
It's cool.
Hey, I'm a friend of Tucker's.
What do you want?
I just want to buy
some of the blue.
It's not for sale.
I know you were
selling it earlier--
Oh, yeah?
How do you know that?
Uh, Tucker told me.
Yeah, Tucker needs to learn
to keep his damn mouth shut.
Tucker! Tucker!
So, uh, you going to hook me up?
Don't have enough
for all of Tucker's friends.
Tucker!
You know, I think he's outside.
You want to just go outside--
Tucker! Tucker!
Hey, hey. Let's go find Tucker.
Okay? Let's go outside.
I don't have enough for you,
all right?
Yeah. yeah.
Yeah, I get it. Okay.
I don't want to start
any trouble.
Trouble? What's that mean?
Trouble?
No, no, no. I'm just saying
we're cool, okay?
We're good.
What?
You can't know that.
What does that mean?
You don't put thoughts
in my head.
Absolutely. You're right.
Tucker?
[MAN GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
JESSE:
You--
[MAN MOANING SOFTLY]
[BELL RINGS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Here you go, Maria.
Veronica.
Ilia, gracias.
So, uh...
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[VERONICA & ILIA LAUGH]
I missed that one.
I'm sure it was good.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[TYRUS AND WOMEN
SPEAKING SPANISH]
WALT:
Wait, where you taking them?
Come on, Tyrus,
what are you doing?
I'm putting them on a bus.
Why? What bus?
One back to Honduras.
Hey, wait a second.
Wait a minute.
Wait, wait. This was my idea.
Don't punish them.
You tell Gus to blame me,
not them.
He does.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY OVER SPEAKERS]
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
Give us a minute, will you?
We won't be too long.
MIKE:
The crew that hit our truck
gave away the cargo
to a couple local nobodies.
Very disciplined of them,
not keeping anything
for themselves.
It was all about
sending a message.
Which they did, literally.
It was written
on the bucket lid.
"Ready to talk?"
That, I believe,
is the English translation.
[SIGHS]
I know you're not really
asking for advice.
But let me hire
10, 15 more good operators.
Then we hit them hard.
Hit them where they live.
No. This war
stays cold for now.
What about their message?
What's the answer?
[SIGHS]
Set up a meeting.
Let's see what they have to say.
How did he do today?
I hear you can handle yourself.
I guess.
Good night.
Hey, excuse me?
Why me?
I like to think
I see things in people.
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
Slow down.
The car is not going anywhere.
Mom.
SKYLER: Hey, sweetheart.
Hi.
WALT JR.: Hey.
SKYLER:
Whoo.
See what's in the driveway?
There you go.
Uh, yeah, I saw.
Hey.
So that's yours, huh?
Yeah.
Dad got it for me.
SKYLER:
Well, that was very nice of him.
WALT JR.:
Yeah.
I know it looks like...
Well, awesome,
but it's super safe.
Dad made sure.
And I promise to always go
the speed limit. Or below.
Way below.
And it gets great gas mileage.
So Dad said I can take it around
the block a few times.
That okay?
Just around the block.
Yeah.
And be careful, okay?
I will.
Bye.
It's really--
It's really great
to have you home, Mom.
WALT:
Hey, seriously,
be careful. Okay?
I will.
Okay.
I guess we should talk.
Well, I think you said plenty
the other day.
Look, about that,
it just...
Did you get
the car wash keys?
Yes. Yes. Here.
Skyler, I may have
overstated things earlier,
and I'm sorry
to be so forward.
But I just--
I want you to know something.
I want you to--
I need you to understand
that you are safe.
You, Junior, Holly.
You are completely safe.
Everything that I do,
everything...
I do it
to protect this family.
So buying that car,
that was protecting your family?
Okay. I...
Maybe it's a little flashy,
but he needed a car.
And I'm his father, and I should
be able to get what he wants.
It goes back.
Tomorrow.
Skyler, it will crush him.
That car directly contradicts
our story.
And if you're so invested
in protecting this family,
it means protecting the story.
What do you think the neighbors
are going to say, Walt?
What about Hank and Marie?
How about the IRS?
What were you thinking, Walt?
I was thinking I wanted
to do something nice for my son.
Look.
I just worry
that he'll blame you for this.
Oh, he will.
Once again,
he'll blame his bitch mother
for taking away what
his loving father has given him,
so thanks for that.
[SIGHS]
But you know what, Walt?
Someone has to protect
this family
from the man
who protects this family.
[♪♪♪]