[VIDEO GAME GUN FIRING]
[MAN GROANING OVER TV]
[GUNSHOTS]
[GROANS]
MAN 1 [OVER TV]:
It came out of nowhere.
You gotta help us.
MAN 2:
Look at all this damn water.
MAN 1:
Yeah, don't drink that.
Ain't no telling
if it's gonna be poison.
[GUNSHOTS]
Nothing new over here.
[MAN GRUNTS]
[GUNSHOT]
[♪♪♪]
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES]
[CAR WASH WHIRRING]
How's Junior?
Exactly what I expected.
He hasn't said a word to me
since we told him
it was going back.
I, um, spoke to the dealership,
they didn't wanna take it.
What?
It's in perfect
condition.
It's-- It's got 17 miles
on the odometer.
SKYLER:
I know. I spent
the better part of an hour
sweet-talking the manager down
to a restocking fee.
Eight hundred dollars.
Eight hundred dollars?
For two days?
Well, the law says they don't
have to take it back at all.
All right,
here's the registration,
the window sticker,
the receipt.
Oh, and make sure you talk
to the general manager.
His name is Glenn.
Glenn.
Call me if there's a problem.
And please just don't--
Don't tangle with anyone.
Fine.
Oh. Bueno, Martin.
Muy bueno.
Walt.
[THE PRETENDERS' "BOOTS
OF CHINESE PLASTIC" PLAYING]
♪ One, two, three, four ♪
[TIRES SCREECHING]
♪ Nam Myoho Renge Kyo Buddha
Please ♪
♪ Can you help a little peasant
That's begging on her knees? ♪
♪ Illusion fills my head
Like an empty can ♪
♪ I spent a million lifetimes
Loving the same man ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Always makes it's way
Back to the heart again ♪
♪ And by the way
You look fantastic ♪
♪ In your boots
Of Chinese plastic ♪
[TIRES SQUEALING]
♪ Hare Krishna
Hare Rama too ♪
♪ Govinda, I am still
In love with you ♪
♪ I see you in the birds
And in the trees ♪
♪ That's why they call me
Krishna Mayee ♪
[ENGINE REVVING]
Oh, shit.
♪ That run through
The vein ♪
♪ Always makes it's way back
To the heart again ♪
♪ And by the way
You look fantastic ♪
♪ In your boots
Of Chinese plastic ♪
[SIGHS]
♪ Hofra told us
We should tolerate ♪
♪ The people and the things
That make me wanna hate ♪
♪ Oh, have a little mixed mercy
On me ♪
♪ This seasoned beauty
In this human pageantry ♪
♪ Jesus Christ came down here
As a living man ♪
♪ If he can live a life
Of virtue then I hope I can ♪
♪ Unto others
As you would have a turn ♪
♪ Back here and repeat until
You learn, learn, learn ♪
♪ Oh, every drop
That run through the vein ♪
♪ Always makes it's way
Back to the heart again ♪
♪ And every dog that lived
His life on a chain ♪
♪ Knows what it's like
Waiting for nothing ♪
♪ And by the way
You look fantastic ♪
♪ In your boots
Of Chinese plastic ♪
[SIGHS]
Yes, hello.
I need a cab.
Yes, thank you.
The name is White.
Uh, I am at the
Pavilion parking lot
on University.
Oh, yes, that's right.
Just south of the airport.
Oh, that would be great,
thank you.
Oh, how long do you think
that would take?
No, I'm sure he'll see me.
Thank you.
SAUL:
Contrition?
Hey, there is total
contrition here.
There's mountains
of contrition.
"Fan-tan-tastic." I will
messenger them over right away.
Oh, and, uh, ahem, about that
other thing unrelated,
yes, I can get you in.
But I gotta warn you,
the eighth hole is murder.
Oh, yeah. You wanna
make it interesting?
Great. Tee time
is 7 a.m. sharp.
Prepare to have your ass
handed to you.
Okay. Bye.
[SIGHS]
He was headed for destruction
of property.
But since it's your
own property,
I sweated him down
to misdemeanor trash burning.
[LAUGHS]
Now, the only thing is,
it's-- It's not gonna be free.
Uh, there's a 5 grand fine,
600 for towing and disposal,
another 3 grand to steam-clean
the blacktop.
So bottom line, your little
joyride's gonna set you back
about 52,000 bucks.
So was it worth it?
I don't need to hear
the blow-by-blow.
Just tell me it's done.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I wake you?
I-- I caught this thing
before it got into the system.
That means your record
stays clean,
the wife never finds out.
I've been working magic here.
I could at least get
an "attaboy."
[SIGHS]
Fine. Rebel without a cause,
give.
What is it? Fring?
WALT:
He will see me dead.
And there's nothing
I can do about it.
All that's left
is to wait.
And we're sure
about this.
Because Pinkman says
he needs you too much.
"Pinkman says."
Oh, "Pinkman says."
Unless...
you could help me find
a third party.
What third party?
Someone who can ameliorate
the situation.
Let's ditch the thesaurus,
all right?
You talking
about a hit man?
Assuming that's still
what they're called.
[IMITATING BUZZER]
Wrong answer.
That's what the kids
call "epic fail."
[SIGHS]
All I would need
is a phone number.
I'd do the rest.
Saul, there'd be
a finder's fee.
A big one.
Look, if you held my feet
to the fire,
I-- I could come up
with a couple names.
One or two guys west of
the Rockies who do this work.
But guess what.
These guys,
they know Mike
and Mike knows them.
Are you telling me Mike knows
everyone who does this?
Who do you think
gave me their names?
Okay, plan B.
Look, we go outside my network.
Craigslist.
Soldier of Fortune.
Let's say we get lucky.
I mean, incredibly lucky,
and find a guy
who's not an undercover cop
or some kind of survivalist
nut-job wannabe.
You gotta ask yourself:
How good is good enough?
Because whatever
goombah we buy
at some point is gonna
come head-to-head with Mike.
And Gus Fring?
Hey, just winging that guy
is not gonna "ameliorate"
your situation.
Not by a damn sight.
I tried to solve this myself,
but I can't get
anywhere near him.
You can't get near him?
Why don't you ask
your partner?
Yeah, I saw him.
And you tell Saul
before you tell me?
Look, he's my lawyer,
same as yours.
Every time I go over there,
Saul hassles me about Mike.
He's still scared the dude's
gonna come break his legs.
So I give him
the latest.
What happened exactly?
I was at a diner
with Mike
and he just shows up.
They send me outside
and the two of them talk.
That's it.
So this is, like,
a regular thing?
[SCOFFS]
How close were you
to him?
Close.
I mean, closer than you and me
right now.
Did he speak to you?
It was over in 10 seconds.
Would you just
answer?
He said he sees things
in people.
What things?
What people?
Me.
He said he sees
something in me.
A month ago, Gus was trying
to kill both of us.
And now he pulls you
out of the lab
and employs you as what?
An assistant gunman?
A tough guy?
Does that make
any sense to you?
He says he sees
something in you.
What kind of game
is he playing?
Does he think
you're that naive?
He can't truly think
that you'd forget--
Well, let alone Gale,
let alone Victor...
and all the horror that goes
along with all of that.
What about this girlfriend
of yours
and her little brother?
I mean, the man looked you
straight in the eye
and told you,
"No more children."
But that very night,
that little boy,
he just--
He winds up...
I mean, Gus can't possibly
think that you'd forget that.
Okay.
I mean, all I'm saying
is that--
Is it possible
that he would think
that you're
that weak-willed?
Drop the sales pitch.
I'll do it.
You'll do what?
I'll kill him.
First chance I get.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Piña colada?
More like stale bubblegum.
Does anyone actually
want their car to smell
like the bottom
of a 6th-grader's desk?
Okay. Hemp? Really?
Yeah, I know.
But you know what they say.
"The customer's
always right."
Ooh, speaking of customer,
it's not too late
to have a grand opening.
I was thinking
huge party, balloons,
bouncy house for the kids.
You know, make a splash,
get on TV.
Let people know they're not
gonna have to face
the eyebrows of doom
when they come in.
Marie, how's Hank doing?
You know what?
He's doing better.
Is he?
Yeah. He--
Lately, his mood's improved
and he's like a maniac
with his PT.
That's fantastic.
Yeah, don't get me wrong,
he's got a long way to go,
but he--
Yeah.
Oh, hey.
Hey.
Hi, Walt.
It's good to see you.
Hey. You too.
Hey, your cashier here
is quite the salesperson.
She just talked me
into something
called the Orbital Paste
Wax Buff.
Oh, yeah, it's very important
to maintain your clear coat.
Boy, once that's goes--
Oh, yeah.
Um, hi.
Hi.
SKYLER:
Bogdan was averaging 19 cars
during rush hour,
and we are already up to 22.
Twenty-two actual cars.
Last night,
I deposited $3800.
Jesus.
How much is that?
Two hundred seventy-four
thousand dollars, give or take.
Give or take?
Yeah.
I haven't counted it.
Wait.
Two hundred and seventy-four--
And-- And this is how often?
Every two weeks.
Thursdays good for a drop-off?
Wait, Walt,
are you telling me
you make $7,125,000 a year?
Seven and a half even,
before expenses.
But I can't--
Th-- This is too much.
So it's more than you thought,
and this is somehow
bad news?
No, that's--
That's not the point.
I mean, there's no car wash
in the world
that could do
this kind of business.
I mean, this is nine
months' work here, minimum.
Seven million? That--
That could take years.
So set some aside.
Save it for a rainy day.
Save it? Where?
Save it where?
I can't go to the bank with it
and I sure can't leave it here.
Oye.
Wait a minute.
Is this all 50s?
Who pays for a car wash
with a 50?
Skyler, I didn't ask you
to do this.
I was under the impression
that you had this under control.
I just didn't expect
this amount of money.
The 50s are
gonna be a problem.
Well, that's what this is,
problem solving.
Skyler, this is a simple
division of labor.
I bring in the money,
you launder the money.
This is what you wanted.
I never wanted any of this.
I've gotta go.
If you want out,
just say that you want out.
Okay, then.
[AIR WHOOSHING]
[AIR TURNED OFF]
[GASPING]
[WHIRRING]
You're telling me
you made this in the lab?
Why not?
Making it in his own lab
seemed appropriate.
There's not much of it.
We had more for Tuco.
It's enough.
This is still
the best way.
You go after him
with a gun,
you'll never get out
of it alive.
But with this,
you slip it
into his food or drink.
There shouldn't be
any taste or smell.
Thirty-six hours later...
A man his age,
working as hard as he does,
no one will be surprised.
What about Mike?
Mike can have his suspicions,
but that's all they'll be.
Please, one homicidal maniac
at a time.
[SIGHS]
I don't know
when I'm gonna see Gus again.
I mean, if ever.
[SNIFFS]
Keep it with you.
When you have
the opportunity,
be ready.
What if they search me?
Will they do that?
It's the wrong way around.
It's my lucky
cigarette.
Well,
whatever you do,
don't smoke it.
WALT JR.:
You-- You know they have
a drive-thru, right?
HANK:
Nah, this is good.
Could use the exercise,
get the blood pumping.
Don't worry, you're not gonna
have to pick me up.
It might take me a while,
but I'll get there.
Jesus, ain't we a pair.
Hey, you must really
like chicken.
V-8, 470 horses,
20-inch rims,
satellite radio, Bluetooth.
Zero to 60 in 4.7 seconds.
Whoa, whoa, what do you mean,
on a lark?
Spur of the moment,
your dad ups and buys you
a brand-new Challenger?
Yeah. I barely got it
around the block,
and Mom said we couldn't
afford it, so they took it back.
Do you know how long I had it?
Fifteen hours.
Well, hey, buddy,
let me tell you something.
When I was your age,
I'd have given my left nut
to drive a car like that
for 15 minutes.
Seriously, how--
How does that happen?
Well, we were looking
at used cars and I kind of--
Ah, you guilted him into it.
Yeah, yeah, I know. I hear you.
You pulled the old, "Poor little
me and my troubles," am I right?
Maybe.
You flew too close
to the sun, my friend.
You'd have let him buy you
a clunker,
you'd be driving now instead
of borrowing mom's hooptie.
Agent Schrader.
Oh, hey, how are you doing?
Well, thank you.
Good to see you.
Walter, Jr.,
do you remember Mr. Fring?
How are you?
Well. Nice to see you again.
It's a pleasure to see you.
You're looking very well.
Yeah, well, you know,
chalk it up to clean living
and, uh, vitamin pills.
[GUS LAUGHS]
I must apologize.
If I had seen you come in,
there would have been
no question
of accepting your money.
In the future, please feel free
to ask for me.
A DEA hero should never
have to pay for a meal
at Pollos Hermanos.
No kidding?
I'll take you up on that,
for sure.
[LAUGHS]
And, uh, how are your
mother and father?
They're--
They're good.
The chicken is great.
Thank you.
If ever you're interested
in rewarding part-time work,
perhaps something after school,
my door is always open.
Sounds good.
HANK:
Oh, I don't know about this one.
He might eat up
all your profits.
Well, I'll let you
finish your meal.
Can I get you
anything else?
A refill, perhaps?
No, thank you.
I'm good.
Sure. Take a Diet Coke,
thank you very much.
Of course.
So where are we going?
Oh, big doings today.
The order of the day
is eyes open, mouth shut.
[CHICKENS PEEPING]
What's up?
Test.
You got me?
Count off.
Let's go.
Right here.
Leave the wrap on, please.
You know how
to make coffee?
Sure.
There you go.
You want a rundown?
Please.
Three guys up at the gate,
two visible, one in the blind.
We got five guys down here
with a backup out of sight.
I got Tyrus down in the tree
line with a Barrett .50.
Planted him there last night,
in case we had
any early arrivals.
[♪♪♪]
I don't have
an extra holster.
You stick this in your pocket.
Keep it out of sight.
You're gonna be here today,
you're gonna have a gun.
It's loaded?
[SIGHS]
I don't wanna see that
in your hand
unless you see me
with mine, understood?
Emergency only.
First car is coming.
All right,
what's the order of the day?
Eyes open, mouth shut.
A lot of guns.
Nobody's asking you
to give up yours.
You wanna sweep the place
before you bring in your guys?
I am the guy.
All right, then.
[IN SPANISH]
Welcome.
Where is the rest
of your party?
[IN SPANISH]
I am the only one coming.
And why is that?
My employers feel
I can adequately represent
their interests.
Please, sit.
This is my offer.
In consideration
of our previous relationship...
I will make
a one-time payment
of 50 million
U.S. dollars.
In return, our business
is concluded.
No further payments.
No further contact.
An absolute severance.
You have no response?
This is my response:
Yes or no?
You know what
the Cartel wants.
Anything else
would be a waste of time.
Is it to be yes...
or no?
A hard way to begin
a negotiation.
This is not a negotiation.
[ENGINE STARTING]
[CAR DOORS CLOSING]
MIKE [IN ENGLISH]:
You got something of mine?
Glove box.
Figure I better teach you
how to shoot.
Could be things
are gonna get hairy.
What is this?
I mean, you're giving me
a gun, and--
And now I'm, like,
part of the team or whatever?
He said he sees
something in me.
Like what?
If I had to put it in a word,
I'd guess loyalty.
Loyalty.
Only maybe you got it
for the wrong guy.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Jesse?
Hey.
Long time, no see.
How you doing?
Yeah, you know, uh...
good.
Good.
Okay, we're gonna get started.
You coming in?
So the truth is,
we can't change the past.
What's done is done.
We've gotta
own our actions,
but putting ourselves
on trial,
acting as our own judge,
jury and executioner,
it's not the answer.
Because a lot of the time,
all that judging does
is just ensure that we're
gonna repeat the cycle.
Right?
"I'm such an asshole.
"It's totally hopeless,
what's the point?
I think I'll have a hit."
Jesse, what's going on
with you these days?
[SIGHS]
I, uh, went back
to the crystal.
You sober now?
Yeah.
Four days.
Big whoop, right?
GROUP LEADER:
Hey, four days is four days.
You're here.
You still...
working at the laundry?
How are things there?
Sucks ass.
[CHUCKLES]
Anything you want
to talk about?
Um...
A couple of weeks back...
I, uh,
killed a dog.
GROUP LEADER:
You hit it with your car?
No, I...
I put him down.
I watched him go.
I was looking him
straight in the eye.
You know, he didn't know
what was happening.
He didn't know why. He...
He was just scared.
And then...
he was gone.
He was suffering.
It was a kindness.
No, he wasn't sick.
No. He was just, like a...
I don't know,
like, a...
problem dog.
What'd he do?
Bite someone?
No, this dog never--
Never bit anybody.
You pick up the rock,
you go right to the dark side.
Anything can happen.
It ain't no rock
that made me do it.
Well, what was the problem?
Why'd you have to kill him?
Watch the crosstalk, please.
Maybe it's not the details
that matter, right?
How'd you feel about
what you did, Jesse?
I don't know.
Who cares how you feel?
What kind of a person
kills a dog for no reason?
GROUP LEADER:
Colleen.
COLLEEN:
Put an ad in the paper,
you drop him off
at a shelter.
Don't sit there and talk about
killing a helpless animal.
We're not here
to sit in judgment.
Why not?
Maybe she's right.
You know, maybe I should've
put it in the paper.
Maybe I-- I should've
done something different.
The thing is,
if you just do stuff
and nothing happens...
what's it all mean?
What's the point?
Oh, right, this-- This whole
thing is about self-acceptance.
Kicking the hell
out of yourself
doesn't give meaning
to anything.
So I should stop judging...
and accept?
GROUP LEADER:
It's a start.
So no matter what I do,
hooray for me
because I'm a great guy?
It's all good?
No matter how many
dogs I kill,
I just, what,
do an inventory and accept?
[SNIFFLES]
I mean, you back your truck
over your own kid
and you, like, accept?
What a load of crap.
Hey, Jesse.
I know you're in pain.
No, you know what?
Why I'm here
in the first place...
is to sell you meth.
You're nothing to me
but customers!
I made you my bitch.
You okay with that?
Huh?
You accept?
No.
About time.
[STEAM HISSING]
[GRUNTS]
[COUGHS]
Jesse.
Bring your light over here,
will you?
Do you see
any residue there?
Where?
Here. On the bottom,
right there.
[WHISPERING]
It's been a week.
What's going on?
I haven't seen him.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I didn't think so.
But I'll just give it
another shot anyway.
[GRUNTS]
[STEAM HISSING]
Hey.
Hey, buddy. Look at that.
Graduated to doorman.
Finally found your calling.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, little whiskers,
Marie.
What'd you do?
Show your barber a picture
of a dog's ass
and said, "I'll take that"?
[LAUGHS]
Yeah, charming as usual.
Welcome back.
Looking good, Marie.
Oh, thanks, Steve.
Good to see you. How you doing?
He's doing fine.
We can take it from here.
Right, Gomie?
Yeah.
If you wanna
hold his elbow.
No, no, no. You keep
your mitts off me.
I'm good. I'm good.
MARIE:
Hey.
Good luck.
Let's go, we're running late.
Come on.
[SIGHS]
Hank, seeing you walk in here,
I can't tell you what that means
to all of us.
Your progress,
it's incredible.
Yeah, well, chalk it up to
clean living and vitamin pills.
[LAUGHS]
Steve tell you his news?
What?
Finally got your period?
I made GS-14.
Wow, that's all right, man.
Next stop: Washington, D.C.
Sitting behind a desk,
papers piled so high
you can't see over them.
Hey, better you than me,
buddy.
Seriously, congratulations,
Thanks.
Steve said you might
have something for us.
Yeah, maybe. You guys are gonna
have to tell me.
You remember my pal
Tim Roberts?
APD detective?
Yeah, well, he's working
on a murder case.
The victim's a 34-year-old
male Caucasian
by the name
of Gale Boetticher.
One night last month,
Boetticher opens the door
and, bam,
takes a bullet to the face from
a person or persons unknown.
Now, this Gale Boetticher
is a bona fide chemistry genius.
I mean, he's got degrees
up the wazoo, right?
And, well, as you might expect,
he's a nerd's nerd.
Vegan, sandals and socks
kind of guy.
As it turns out, he's also
an A-number-one meth cook.
And what caught my eye is
his specialty product's blue.
So, what are you thinking?
This is your Heisenberg?
No. What I think
we got here is, ahem,
Heisenberg's former cook,
and maybe a line
on Heisenberg himself.
Anyway, lo and behold,
amidst all the hippie-dippy
nonsense,
I find this.
Now, this here,
I do a little Google-fu,
and I realize
it's a parts number
specifically for this baby.
Now that there
is a high-volume
HEPA industrial
air filtration system.
That's a $300,000 gadget.
Perfect for a pharmaceutical
plant or microchip factory,
or maybe the biggest meth lab
north of the border.
Okay.
So this little dingus here
is manufactured
by a big international concern:
Madrigal Electromotive.
I call their Houston office,
and eventually I get through
to the nicest little
20-year-old temp.
I use some of the Schrader
sweet-talk on her,
before you know it,
she's pulling files.
Turns out
six months ago,
one of these systems was shipped
to a depot right here in ABQ.
Who signed for it?
Gale Boetticher.
So I asked my new girlfriend,
"Who paid for it?"
And she says, "Nobody."
[SCOFFS]
They have no record that anybody
actually paid for this thing.
So I go back and push more
and before you know it,
the temp's gone,
there's no forwarding address.
and I'm talking to some
snot-nose lawyer
who's asking me
for my badge number.
Brick wall.
So I take a peek
into Madrigal Electromotive.
Now, Madrigal is based
in Hanover, Germany,
but they're what they call
"highly diversified."
Industrial equipment,
global shipping,
major construction,
and a tiny little foothold
in American fast food,
specifically
a local chain.
Pollos Hermanos.
Okay. So what, right?
Boetticher's dead.
I got no line on who's
been bankrolling him
or where his lab was.
The whole thing's
a snipe hunt, right?
But now I get this crazy idea,
and I can't shake it.
I mean, I-- I stay up nights
staring at the ceiling
trying to make sense of it.
That napkin. Remember, I told
you Boetticher's a vegan.
I mean, we're talking
this guy makes his own
fermented lentil bread,
or whatever the hell that is.
What's a vegan doing
in a fried chicken joint?
Maybe he's meeting somebody.
Like who?
Well, like, maybe...
this guy.
I mean, what do we know
about Gustavo Fring, huh?
This whole
friend-of-law-enforcement thing?
Could be a case of,
"keep your friends close
but your enemies closer."
I mean, he's got the money
to finance this operation.
Maybe he's got the connections
too. Maybe, just maybe,
he's our guy.
Hank, no offense,
but I think you're
really reaching.
If your guy had his meeting
at KFC,
you wouldn't
immediately assume
that he's sitting down
with Colonel Sanders.
You know, I-- Ahem.
I couldn't agree more, guys.
[CHUCKLES]
Gustavo Fring, blue meth,
you know.
The whole thing
is off-the-map nuts.
I ought to be wearing
a tinfoil hat, you know?
Except...
I can't seem to wrap my mind
around this one little thing.
And that is,
what are Gustavo Fring's
fingerprints...
doing in Gale Boetticher's
apartment?
[♪♪♪]