Are we done?
WALT: Listen, I--
This attack on my
brother-in-law,
I don't know
what it means.
Please.
I fear for my family.
I'm sure
they'll be fine.
I am told the assassin that
survived is gravely injured.
It's doubtful he'll live.
Now, thank me
and shake my hand.
Thank you.
Thank you again.
You're quite welcome,
Mr. White.
Can we go now?
Upstairs, come on.
[ALL CLAMORING]
What's happening?
[EKG FLATLINING]
MAN: Eight forty-three.
WOMAN:
Time of death, 20:43.
Burn in hell,
you piece of shit.
[♪♪♪]
NEWS ANCHOR [OVER TV]:
One of the suspected gunmen
died at the scene.
The second succumbed to his
wounds earlier this evening.
Agents with the DEA and FBI,
in conjunction with APD
homicide detectives,
are working with Mexican
law enforcement
in an attempt to identify
the deceased suspects. Both--
I can give you
the highlights.
Your nephews
grew impatient.
They continued
to press me
for my permission
to kill Walter White.
When I wouldn't give it,
they settled instead
for DEA Agent Schrader.
But a phone call was placed
to Agent Schrader
moments before the attack.
Thus giving him
the upper hand.
Marco was shot in the face
and died instantly.
Leonel lingered
for several hours.
The warning call
to the DEA agent,
Juan Bolsa may have
some insight
into who placed it.
Yesterday, the federales
raided his hacienda.
And in the confusion,
Juan was shot dead.
An accident, perhaps.
A mistake made
by his own men.
Though we may never know.
At any rate, I thought
you should hear it from me.
This is what comes
of blood for blood, Hector.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[♪♪♪]
[EASY-LISTENING MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
So is this
the loud one?
What?
I can never remember.
Is this the loud machine
with the magnets?
No. This is
the PET/CT scan.
Positron emission
tomography.
They've paired that with
computed x-ray tomography.
Quiet. No magnets.
Right, okay.
Yeah, thanks.
I'm still pretty new
at this.
I mean, one minute,
I'm starting a new business,
my wife and I
are thinking about kids.
Walk into a doctor's office
and suddenly...
[MAN IMITATES EXPLOSION]
I mean, life as I know it--
Excuse me.
Yes. I'm-- I'm waiting
to hear a progress report
on the thing we discussed,
so call me.
Anyway, so for me, that's been
the biggest wake-up call.
Letting go,
giving up control.
You know, it's like they say,
"Man plans and God laughs."
That is such bullshit.
Excuse me?
Never give up control.
Live life
on your own terms.
Yeah, no,
I get what you're saying,
but cancer
is cancer, so...
To hell with
your cancer.
I've been living with cancer
for the better part of a year.
Right from the start,
it's a death sentence.
That's what they keep
telling me.
Well, guess what?
Every life comes
with a death sentence.
So every few months, I come in
here for my regular scan,
knowing full well
that one of these times--
Hell, maybe even today.
--I'm gonna hear
some bad news.
But until then,
who's in charge?
Me.
That's how I live
my life.
This residue here is why
we descale with cool water
from the walk-in
and not water from the tap.
[PHONE RINGING]
Do it again, please.
Pollos Hermanos, where something
delicious is always cooking.
Yes, detective.
[OFFICERS CHATTERING]
Yeah.
[DOOR CLOSES]
MERKERT:
Gustavo, thanks for coming.
How's Kathi?
Much better, thank you.
And you know
Hank Schrader?
Oh, yes, indeed.
And Steve Gomez?
How was your meal?
Agent Schrader and I
had a chance to catch up
at one of my restaurants
a few days ago.
I'd eat there every day but
I wouldn't fit through the door.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
Well, should we get started?
HANK: Yeah.
ROBERTS:
I'd like to record this
conversation.
GUS:
Of course.
[RECORDER BEEPS]
The DEA is working
on an investigation
which may overlap
with my own,
so I've asked them to sit in
with us today.
Gus, we all appreciate your
coming in here to talk to us,
but you have the right to have
an attorney present also.
Oh, well, I can't see
how that would be necessary.
But then again,
I have no idea why I'm here.
So you wish to continue?
Please. I'm very anxious to find
out what this is all about.
Sir, your fingerprints
were found at a crime scene.
Really?
That's surprising.
ROBERTS:
A drug-related homicide.
[SIGHS]
Gale Boetticher's apartment.
So you knew the victim?
Fifteen years ago, I established
a chemistry scholarship at UNM.
I named it
after Maximino Arciniega,
a dear friend of mine
who died too young.
Gale was a recipient
of this scholarship.
He was perhaps
one of three dozen.
I see.
And Mr. Boetticher
graduated in...
1999.
That sounds right.
And you kept in contact with him
over all this time?
Oh, no. I hadn't
seen Gale for years
until I ran into him
a few weeks ago.
Ran into him where?
At the restaurant.
Uh, well, "ran into"
isn't quite accurate,
as I assumed he came by
to re-establish contact with me.
We caught up briefly.
He invited me to dinner the
following night and I accepted.
It was perhaps a week later when
I read about him in the paper.
Drug related, you said?
MERKERT:
It's a good possibility.
The paper made
no mention of that.
I assumed
that it was a random crime.
HANK:
So after years with no contact,
he shows up
in your restaurant,
remakes your acquaintance
and invites you to dinner?
He wanted money.
Gale Boetticher
asked for money?
GUS:
He didn't come out and say that.
He spoke in terms of a vague
investment opportunity.
But it was my suspicion, yes,
as to why he invited me
into his home.
He was a very,
very talented chemist.
But for reasons
I never understood,
he was more interested
in taking shortcuts
than what would or could have
been a very promising career.
But personal shortcomings
notwithstanding,
he was a warm, gentle person,
and I thought a lot of him.
At any rate, I, uh,
declined his business offer.
And after what was a very
pleasant meal, left.
ROBERTS:
Can you tell us where you were
on the night of Wednesday
the 23rd at around 8 p.m.?
Not an accusation,
just a question.
No, I understand.
Let's see.
Twenty-third.
Ah. I was at a fundraiser
at Presbyterian Hospital.
I was there
from 7 to about 10.
Anyone else?
Uh, sorry, yeah. Just, uh--
Just one other thing.
Is Gustavo Fring
your real name?
Is it my real name?
I know you're a Chilean
national,
but there are no records of you
ever living there.
Really?
I mean, records show that you
immigrated to Mexico in 1986,
and then a couple years later,
you were granted an entry visa
to the United States.
But there's no record
of Gustavo Fring
ever having existed in Chile,
which I find,
I don't know, strange.
Well, no,
really, it isn't.
Pinochet's government
was guilty of a great many sins.
First and foremost
were human rights abuses.
But it was also notoriously
unreliable at keeping records.
I'm sure if you keep digging,
you'll find me.
Okay, I think that's it, Gus.
Um, thank you.
I hope that I was
of some small help.
You were, absolutely.
Thank you.
You're very welcome.
Good to see you again.
Oh, no.
No, please, please.
Don't get up.
Thanks.
Gentlemen.
[DOOR OPENS]
[ELEVATOR DINGING]
So are we buying?
This thing with his name?
What are you thinking there?
Sure, the record-keeping
in South America's hit or miss.
I mean, we run into that
all the time, right?
But we usually
find something.
I mean, before '86
this guy's a ghost.
If State Department wasn't
satisfied with his records,
they wouldn't
have naturalized him.
Well, maybe, but he emigrated
from Mexico in '89.
State just wasn't as tough
on background checks pre-9/11.
GOMEZ:
Regardless, I don't know what
this has to do
with the case at hand.
I was definitely curious
when his print showed up
at Boetticher's apartment.
But for me, the scholarship
thing explains it.
MERKERT:
Well, I'll admit to a certain
degree of bias.
This man has been
a longtime friend of DEA.
But that being said,
uh, I thought his story
was credible.
Well, I agree.
I think it was a good story.
Still, why are we
hearing it now?
MERKERT:
What do you mean?
Well, like you said,
he's a--
This man is a big
law enforcement booster.
One day he's reading
the newspaper
and sees that someone
he just had dinner with,
someone he thought
a lot of, was murdered.
He reads this and he doesn't
make a phone call?
Didn't call you or one of his
other cop friends
to share his connection
with the case
or ask about
the investigation?
We can't predicate
a criminal investigation
on a person
not making phone calls.
What do you think, Tim?
Well, I wanna
follow up
on the scholarship,
the alibi,
but my overall
impression?
I believed him.
Nice touch.
Birdbath. Ha.
Hey, tiger,
how's it hanging?
Good.
Yeah, so very nice.
What's the damage?
Twelve hundred a month.
I did a lot of research,
and for this neighborhood
that's a pretty good deal.
You kidding me?
That's a great deal.
Speaking of which,
ahem, that's for the week.
Plus there's a little extra
in there
for any move-related
incidentals.
Thank you.
Hey, champ,
how's the new school?
Good.
SAUL: I loved school
when I was your age.
Ha, seesaws, story time,
chasing girls with sticks.
[SAUL LAUGHS]
It wasn't until
the fifth grade
that I found out
she liked me too.
but by then her family
had moved to Scottsdale, so...
[SIGHS]
Carpe diem, okay?
Okay.
All right.
Good boy. Ha!
So you'll thank Jesse again
from both of us?
You got it.
So is he--?
How's he doing?
Jesse?
[SIGHS]
He's good.
He's, uh-- He's busy.
How is it?
Space, lots of light. It's--
Little garden out back.
It's nice.
[SIGHS]
And Brock?
How's he doing?
Hey, look, I don't mind dropping
checks off every week
like Ed McMahon,
but if you really wanna know
how they're doing,
why don't you go see
for yourself?
I'll catch you later.
Hey, you gonna need
a ride home?
JESSE:
No.
[♪♪♪]
[VACUUM WHIRRING]
[SIGHS]
Great.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
SKYLER:
Anyway, I'm proud for not
losing my cool.
Plus, it shows our wipe-down
crew that I will support them
if a customer's being
really rude to them.
You're really taking to this
whole be-your-own-boss thing.
Yeah. I guess I am.
Actually,
I'm thinking about making
the move up to management.
Oh, Jesus. Corporate America,
look out.
Oh, excuse me,
I would be a vast improvement.
No one in Kleinman's entire
front office
knows the first thing
about giving an x-ray,
which just-- Ugh.
Hey, Dad, whatever happened
with your scan?
Did you get the results back?
WALT:
Yeah.
I did.
And I'm still in remission.
So you're all gonna
have to be stuck with me
for a while longer.
HANK: Cheers, buddy.
What about you, Hank?
How you feeling these days?
You know, getting there.
MARIE:
The other day,
he had a big powwow
with all the DEA
muckety-mucks.
WALT:
What was that about?
Nothing. Just a dead-end.
MARIE:
He won't tell me, either.
Apparently, it's all
very hush-hush.
HANK:
Hey, Walt, do me a favor?
Marie's working tomorrow and
there's a gem and mineral show
that's opening
at the fairgrounds.
I was wondering if you
could maybe give me a lift?
Yeah. Sure.
WALT:
I had a collection of my own
back in high school.
I mean, nothing fancy.
Just entry-level beryls
and garnets,
one passable black
tourmaline.
Turn right here.
Okay.
But I did have one piece
of morganite
that was very special.
It'd been heat-treated,
so it had that
classic cast to it.
That rose, almost salmon hue,
you know?
Hey, Walt,
there's no rock show, okay?
I just said that
so Marie wouldn't freak.
Here. Take a right here.
Freak about what?
Hank, where are we going?
Are you hungry?
HANK:
We're not here for the chicken.
Kill the engine.
[TURNS OFF ENGINE]
All right.
[CHUCKLES]
You ready for
your mind to be blown?
Uh, sure.
Gustavo Fring.
Remember him?
He came to the hospital
after the shooting
to put up the reward?
He sponsors the DEA Fun Run
every year. You've met him?
Yeah, the Fun Run guy. Yeah.
That guy, yeah.
What about him?
Well, I suspect--
I can't prove it,
mind you, but I suspect,
the man's a drug dealer.
Hm.
Yeah. Methamphetamine.
I mean, honest to God,
I really believe
that this guy may be one of the
biggest movers in the southwest.
Remember Gale Boetticher?
That sad sack
from the karaoke videotape?
Yeah.
And you said
that he didn't strike you
as being the boss-man type?
That there was a much bigger
guy out there, right?
Hank, that was--
That was just speculation.
It doesn't matter.
It made me keep at it.
And guess what I find?
Chicken Man's fingerprints
at Boetticher's murder scene.
So we bring him in--
You think that Gustavo Fring
killed Gale Boetticher?
Well, probably not.
These guys usually get a dunce
to pull the trigger, right?
His fingerprints being there was
enough for us to bring him in.
So you brought him in
to the police?
Right. He sits down to talk
with us. The problem is that--
What did you ask him?
What did he say?
Walt, will you let me
finish my story here?
Sorry, I'm just, uh,
interested, you know?
All right. Whatever.
So we bring him in
and he proceeds
to kick our asses.
Okay? He's got an explanation
for the fingerprints, all right?
He's got an alibi
for Gale's murder.
I mean, he's got reasons
for everything.
This guy is
Terms of Endearment convincing.
So-- So he's not guilty?
Yeah. As far as DEA
and APD are concerned, he's not.
Officially,
Fring's not a suspect.
But I'm telling you,
something deep down
says he's my guy.
I just gotta prove it.
Hank, why are you--?
Why are you telling me this?
I need a favor.
What favor?
You see that Volvo
station wagon over there?
I mean, the guy drives
a 10-year-old Volvo.
It's brilliant.
Anyway, listen...
[SIGHS]
...what I need
for you to do...
...stick this on it.
GPS tracker.
You know, wifey thinks
hubby's screwing around on her
but she wants to be sure?
Stick this on the car--
This part here, it's a magnet.
--and see where he goes.
Cool, huh?
Two eighty-nine
from SkyMall.
[LAUGHS]
Unfortunately,
it's not live-view,
so we gotta come back later and,
you know, take it off
and stick it
in the computer.
Still, pretty amazing times
we're living in.
Hank, isn't that illegal?
I mean,
isn't there some sort
of unlawful search
and something--
It's known as extralegal.
But trust me,
it's our little secret.
[CHUCKLES]
Look, it's easy, okay?
Here's what you do.
You untie your shoelace and you
head toward the restaurant.
As you're walking
past the car,
you look down and, "Hey, darn,
my shoe's untied." Okay?
Now, when you bend down
to tie your shoe,
you stick this
up into the wheel well.
Then you go inside
and I don't know--
Hank, I-- I don't-- I don't feel
good about this at all.
Look, Walt, I-- I know
that this kind of thing
is outside
your comfort zone--
No, I mean it.
This is a mistake.
Walt, I need you to help me
out here, okay?
I mean, this is really
important to me.
Jesus, are you gonna
make me beg you?
Come on.
Just stick it in there.
Yeah.
Just act normal.
May I help you?
I-- I--
Sir, may I help you?
I didn't do it. See?
I didn't do it.
Do it.
May I help you
with your order?
[MUMBLES INDISTINCTLY]
What the hell is he...?
Just, uh, made sure
it was secure.
[GRUNTS]
Hey, where's my soda?
Just kidding.
Let's go. Let's go.
[ENGINE STARTS]
MAN:
Yes, that one.
[♪♪♪]
Look, I swear to God,
I thought I was driving the man
to a gem and mineral show.
And all of a sudden he has me
pulling into your restaurant
and telling me
that he's investigating you.
Look, you and I,
we've had our differences,
but I would never--
Look, my brother-in-law,
evidence-wise, has nothing.
He's operating
on pure conjecture.
And no one, not one person
that he works with,
thinks that you are anyone
other than an owner
of a fast-food chain.
But if something
were to happen to Hank,
then that would only draw
their attention to you
and therefore,
to me, as well.
So we have
a mutual interest
in resolving this
without violence.
I will make sure
that he discovers nothing.
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Jesse!
What? Oh, hey.
Don't wait to be, like, invited.
Are we alone?
So where do we stand?
Where do we stand
on what?
Where do we stand with the thing
that you were supposed to do?
I assume you haven't done it.
You didn't lose it,
did you?
You would tell me
if you lost it, right?
Oh, Jesus.
Asshole. You're creaming to get
it done, go do it yourself.
If he didn't see me coming
like he's some kind of...
All right, look.
Our timetable has advanced.
You have got to make
this meeting happen this week.
Tomorrow.
Tonight, if possible.
Oh, tonight. Wow.
What are you, high?
My brother-in-law,
my DEA agent brother-in-law?
He's onto Gus.
Huh.
Did you hear what I just said?
My brother-in-law is onto Gus.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I got it,
your brother-in-law.
Okay? I'm thinking.
[SIGHS]
Look, um...
So, what if this is
like math or algebra?
We add a plus douche bag
to a minus douche bag
and you get, like,
zero douche bags.
I've got some math for you.
Hank catching Gus
equals Hank catching us.
Hank is-- He's relentless,
all right?
He won't quit.
Yeah, well, he's got nothing,
is all I can say.
How would you know that?
Because he's still
above ground.
Think a dude like Gus would let
your boy anywhere near him?
He'll break out his box cutter
on his sorry gimp ass.
So you haven't even seen him
since that time at the diner?
Okay.
Think. All right.
They've got to be figuring
that we've talked.
So you need to tell Mike
that you are worried
about Hank's investigation.
Okay? Hank already knows
who you are, by the way.
And besides, you actually
did kill Gale,
so there's that.
This is all good fodder for you
to request a sit-down with Gus,
so you can discuss
what you would say
in case Hank brings you in
for questioning.
Okay? Now, you just-- You just
say that you want to be--
No, that-- That you need to be
able to be properly coached.
Then, when you're near him,
you put this to use.
Mike's just gonna tell me to
shut my mouth if I get busted.
He ain't gonna set up
no meeting.
Well, then insist on it,
damn it!
Act panicked.
Gus' ass is on the line.
And trust me,
he will meet with you
if he thinks
that you're a liability.
No. He will waste me
if he thinks I'm a liability.
[SNIFFS]
You know what?
Whatever, man.
I'm gonna take a piss.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PHONE CHIMES]
[TOILET FLUSHES]
[DOOR OPENS]
I think you, uh,
got a phone call.
Anything important?
[SIGHS]
[PHONE BUZZING]
Yes?
MIKE:
I did some digging around.
And?
Neither the DEA
nor the APD considers you
a person of interest.
Schrader's looking into you
totally on his lonesome.
A voice in the wilderness.
Does he have resources?
Just him, his credit card
and his chauffeur Walter.
From what I head, he'd be
committing career suicide
if he were to mention you
to Merkert again.
GUS:
So no warrant for
the tracking device on my car?
No. The guy's gone
totally maverick.
He's Miss Daisy
with binoculars.
We watch our backs, make sure
we don't throw him any bones.
He'll never make a case.
What about Chile?
If I can't find
any trace of you before '89,
I seriously doubt
Schrader can.
Seems to me the bigger problem
is the cartel.
Now, we can handle them
if that's all we've got
on our plate.
But dealing with both Schrader
and the Mexicans
at the same time?
If he happens to be watching
when they make a move,
it could be
the perfect storm.
Thank you.
I'll be in touch.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
MAN [ON RADIO]:
I don't know how many grandmas
and grandpas we got.
Is there a couple of them
out there in viewing land?
Well, it's
"The Grandparent's Polka."
[FRITZ'S POLKA BAND'S
"GRANDPARENT'S POLKA"
PLAYING OVER RADIO]
GUS:
Hello, Hector.
The cartel has given me
its ultimatum.
To which I've said no.
DEA Agent Schrader,
he's a concern.
He's looking into my past.
♪ Now it's time to do
The grandparent's polka ♪
♪ And maybe tell
A story or two ♪
♪ About the great times
That we had together ♪
♪ And all the things
That we used to do ♪
Is today the day, Hector?
MAN [IN SPANISH]:
Gustavo, sit down.
You're making me nervous.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
It's a good plan.
Trust yourself.
Everything is going
to be okay.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[FLY UNZIPS]
[TIO URINATING]
[IN SPANISH]
Are you crazy?
The boss is gonna
rip your balls off!
[IN SPANISH]
What, you gonna tell?
And you?
They ain't gonna
say nothing.
They like what they see.
BOLSA:
You're not going to offer
our guests anything?
Who says they're guests?
If the boss wants them
to drink,
they drink.
BOLSA:
So...the Chicken Brothers.
I like your restaurant.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Dark meat and white meat?
Don't look like
no brothers to me.
DON ELADIO [IN SPANISH]:
At last! The master chefs!
[DON ELADIO CHUCKLES]
You two...
That chicken you cook...
I swear, it has got to be
the tastiest chicken
in all of Mexico.
Thank you, Don Eladio.
It's a great honor.
Max is the chef.
The compliments are all his.
Gustavo is too modest.
There'd be no restaurant
without him.
Well, however you two do it,
keep it up.
Your chicken, it's so...zesty.
Piquant.
But it does not taste
like a Mexican style.
It's a recipe
I learned in Chile
which I've modified a bit
for the Mexican palate.
I bet we like a little more
chili than you Chileans.
We Mexicans like
a good hard kick!
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[MAX SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
So...if your partner
is the chef,
then who are you?
Don't tell me
you are just the taster!
I handle the business
operations.
MAX:
Gustavo is a brilliant
businessman.
Ahh. Es el businessman.
Ha, ha.
Good, good. Mm.
But tell me something.
That chicken, so fabulous,
so excellent...
Besides that, what else
do you have on your menu?
We have several
side dishes.
Rice. Beans.
Sometimes we prepare
a carnitas entrée
if we come across
fresh beef in the market.
DON ELADIO:
Anything else?
Come on, be honest.
There is nothing else you offer?
A little taste
of something else?
Something on the side?
Because when I send my men
to your restaurant,
they come back
with more than just chicken.
They come back with drugs.
Regresan high.
[DON ELADIO SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You are selling them narcotics.
Methamphetamine.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
With all due respect,
Don Eladio.
I didn't sell it to them.
I gave them samples.
Samples.
Some businessman.
I gave them samples
to give to you.
To introduce you
to our product.
MAX:
Don Eladio,
Gustavo meant no offense.
But he...
That is to say we
could think of no other way
to get your attention.
We want to work with you,
Don Eladio.
I know all about
methamphetamine.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
That's poor man's cocaine.
Only bikers
and hillbillies use it.
There's no money in it.
May I, Don Eladio...
I am a biochemist
by training.
The methamphetamine we make
is much superior
to the so-called biker crank
you know of.
It is crystallized,
like glass.
Purer.
And the chirality
of the molecule,
its very structure,
is different.
The narcotic effect
is far more potent.
This product is the drug
of the future.
Ahh.
GUS:
It'll triple your profits.
Perhaps quadruple.
[DON ELADIO LAUGHS]
They're not only good cooks,
they're great at
shoveling manure.
[DON ELADIO, TIO & BOLSA
LAUGHING]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Right now, you deal almost
exclusively with cocaine.
But the coca plant
can't grow in Mexico.
You are no more than middlemen
for the Colombians.
They cut you a percentage for
smuggling across the border.
But the lion's share
of the profits goes to them
despite your assumption
of all the risk.
This new
crystal methamphetamine...
It's stronger,
more addictive than cocaine,
which means it will move
in higher volume.
But most importantly,
it's completely artificial.
We can show you
how to manufacture it
right here in Mexico.
And you keep all the profits.
My men do like your product.
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Hector, what is wrong with you?
Why did you not get glasses
for our guests?
Go on.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You are quite the talent.
I bet you learned cooking
from your mama. Isn't that true?
[DON ELADIO SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
But...what about the chemistry?
I studied at
the University of Santiago.
Gustavo paid
for my education.
Oh, really?
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
I have degrees
in both biochemistry
and chemical engineering.
With minimal
capital investment,
we can set up a factory-grade
laboratory for you.
Train your own people
to manufacture large quantities
of highly pure
methamphetamine.
Fantastic!
Tell me one thing, though.
If you're the cook...
Why do I need him?
Señor?
You.
[IN ENGLISH]
Businessman.
[IN SPANISH]
Why should I negotiate with
someone who doesn't respect me?
Who insults me by
dealing under my nose
without my permission?
Who manipulates me
into a meeting
in front of my own men?
What do I need you for?
GUS:
Don Eladio. Please.
I didn't sell anything.
I apologize
if you are offended
by my method
of obtaining this meeting.
I merely
took the initiative.
I meant no insult.
MAX:
Don Eladio,
Gustavo didn't mean to offend.
I know Gustavo like a brother.
He's an honorable man.
The most loyal man
I have ever known.
He rescued me
from the Santiago slums.
He made me
the man I am today!
Gustavo is a genius.
He will make you millions!
Just find it
in your heart
to forgive him this
one small mistake.
Please...
[STAMMERS]
He's my partner.
I need him! I swear to God!
[GUNSHOT]
[♪♪♪]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[GRUNTING THEN YELLING]
Look at him.
You did this to him.
Now, look at him.
[GUS GRUNTING]
[SOBBING]
Listen to me.
The only reason you are alive
and he is not
is because I know who you are.
But understand...
You are not in Chile anymore.
TIO:
My advice...
Stick to chicken.
Huh?
[GUS PANTING]
[GUS GRUNTING]
[GUS YELLING AND SOBBING]
[ON RADIO]
♪ Right here
In Verona with you ♪♪
[IN ENGLISH]
Look at me, Hector.
Look at me.
Maybe next time.
[♪♪♪]