[♪♪♪]
[WALT BREATHING HEAVILY]
[CAR DOOR BEEPING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
I got it, I got it.
You're like a bee
at a damn picnic, Marie.
[IMITATING BEE BUZZING]
Morning.
Hey, buddy.
Ready to get
your rocks on?
See? I knew it.
"Mineral show" is just some sort
of guy code for "strip club."
Yeah. You got
your singles?
Got it?
Yeah.
Don't let him get
too crazy, okay?
Cram one more
giant geode in here,
we'll be sleeping
in the garage.
HANK: Got it. I got it.
I'm sorry.
[GRUNTS]
HANK:
Christ. Longest week ever.
[HANK LAUGHS]
Here's just hoping we get
something good.
Keep your fingers
crossed.
Relax, buddy,
this ain't no spy movie.
[CHUCKLES]
It's more like Rocky,
you know?
[HUMMING "EYE OF THE TIGER"]
HANK:
♪ Get the bad guy ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ 'Cause it's the eye
Of the tiger ♪
♪ It's the thrill
Of the fight ♪
♪ Risin' up ♪
[MUMBLING LYRICS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[CUTS IGNITION]
But-- What are you
doing, buddy?
Leaving.
No, go inside,
order something like last time.
Avoid suspicion.
Besides, I want
a vanilla shake.
We'll use the drive-thru.
All right, baby,
let's see what we got.
What the hell?
Look at this.
Bum, bum, bum, bum, bum.
That's work. That's home.
That's work, that's home.
What, this guy...
he goes two places
every day, all week?
It's unbelievable.
Chicken-slinging
son of a bitch.
Hank, is it possible
that maybe, just maybe,
he's not your guy?
A guy this clean
has got to be dirty.
[SIGHS]
What's the play here, buddy?
How do I get this guy?
Yeah.
How?
[♪♪♪]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[DIALING]
Yes, hi.
I live on the 4900 block
of Doswell Place,
and I want to report
a very suspicious man who's
lurking in my neighborhood.
He's sitting in a blue sedan,
and he--
He's been staring
at a particular house
for a very long time.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
If you would,
I would appreciate it.
All right.
I guess we'd better
get started.
I already did.
Yeah?
Hey, uh...
Got one of those for me?
One of those what?
Cigarette.
[SCOFFS]
Look, it's still in there,
all right?
I didn't get a chance yet.
Just give me one.
[COUGHS]
Hm!
So, what have you been up to?
What?
You know, just a day
in the life.
What do you do
after work?
Go home. Watch TV.
What do you watch?
I don't know, stuff.
Well, like what?
Like, uh, Ice Road Truckers.
Ice Road Truckers.
What happens on that one?
Guys drive on ice.
[CHUCKLES]
I am gonna do it.
You gotta inhale,
by the way.
What the hell, man?
Don't you have enough
cancer already?
Look.
I said...
I'd do it. I'll do it.
Yeah, well,
what does it matter?
We're both dead men
anyway.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[CALCULATOR WHIRRING]
[BUTTONS TAP]
[BEEPS]
[PHONE LINE RINGS]
WALT [OVER PHONE]: Hi.
Hi.
Am I, uh, catching you
at a bad time?
No. I have a few minutes.
So Mr.
I'm-Almost-16-So-Leave-Me-Alone
doesn't want a big thing
for his birthday.
Wants to hang out with friends.
Which is fine by me. You?
Fine by me.
Okay. So I figured
a low-key family dinner,
no official party,
and we bite the bullet
and buy him a car.
Used, I was thinking,
would be best.
But no more
than five years old.
Airbags, safety-rated,
all that.
Do you, um, have
any thoughts on what kind?
Or should I just
go ahead and--?
Yeah.
No, you just go ahead.
Okay.
Listen, on another subject,
I just wanted to tell you
that business is good.
Really good.
So good that
I'm thinking, maybe,
you don't need to even work
your second job.
You're turning a profit?
We're coming close.
Give us another
month or two and, yeah,
we'll be there.
All of this to say,
maybe you could start thinking
about an exit strategy.
I'm working on it.
Okay.
[BEEPS OFF]
[RINGING]
[WALT GRUNTS]
Hello?
HANK [OVER PHONE]:
Hey, buddy. Wake you?
No, Hank. I'm up.
Oh, good.
Uh, what you doing?
I'm....
Hey, listen, I'll cut to it.
Another favor to ask.
I'm thinking about Gus Fring,
how he never goes anywhere.
One restaurant, home,
back and forth?
Which now I'm even more
convinced is bullshit,
because the man owns
13 other restaurants, right?
So I started thinking about this
little empire of his, right?
Fourteen restaurants.
Who supplies them?
What's the base
of operations?
So I do a little digging,
and bingo.
Pollos Hermanos
has a main distribution center.
Uh, it's not far from town.
The place is huge.
I mean,
I'm looking at it
online right now.
It's a--
It's a big warehouse.
And rows of these long
poultry buildings,
or hatcheries,
or whatever you call them.
Lots of space to hide
illicit activity.
Sounds promising, right?
Huh.
So, what do you say, buddy?
Got another
field trip in you?
[HANK CHUCKLES]
Uh...
You know, Hank,
I'm-- I'm-- I'm--
I mean, It sounds great,
it really does.
But I'm--
You know, I won't lie.
You caught me somewhat...
indisposed.
What do you mean, like--
Like taking-a-dump indisposed?
Yeah. That's...
Embarrassingly, that's it.
You know, it's just...
[SIGHS]
...upset stomach and,
you know, everything--
Yeah.
It's out of control.
And it's really explosive.
Bad Tex-Mex at the mall.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I get it.
You don't have
to paint me a picture.
One guy in a diaper
is enough for this trip.
Yeah, and I'm sorry, Hank.
Don't be. I've been
asking a lot of you lately.
I appreciate it.
I'll find another ride
for this.
Another ride?
Yeah. I can get
someone else to take me.
Uh, my trainer, Chuck.
Maybe I'll-- I'll ask him.
Well, look, I'm-- This is
probably just a 24-hour thing.
Maybe 48 hours
at the most.
And, um, do you think
you can possibly
hold off for a day or two?
Oh, jeez, buddy,
I mean, I...
You know, I just--
I would just really
love to be the one
to be able to take you there.
And-- And, I mean,
I've just-- I've just really
enjoyed, you know,
the time with you
and helping you and--
Well, yeah.
Okay, sure.
If it means that much to you.
[CHUCKLES]
Just, you know, give me a call
when you're feeling up to it.
Thank you.
I-- I will. Okay.
Bye.
[PHONE BEEPS OFF]
[DIALING]
[PHONE LINE RINGING]
MIKE [OVER PHONE]:
Yeah.
Uh, Mike, listen.
I just want to say first off,
don't be angry.
What is it, Walter?
My brother-in-law,
my DE-- He...
Soon, he will probably,
in the near future,
take a ride out to a certain
distribution center
to look around
for things.
You know, just...
look around for things.
And, yeah.
[PHONE LINE CLICKS]
Mike?
Where's this all going?
Elsewhere.
[STEAM HISSING]
All set. Please give this
to your car-care professional.
Thank you.
[THOMAS DOLBY'S "HYPERACTIVE"
PLAYING OVER RADIO]
So a hand wax
for you today?
Okay, great.
Give this to
your car-care professional.
And the black Explorer...
We could shampoo
your floor mats,
but deluxe detailing
is the best bang for your buck.
Oh, and SUV's are extra.
And please give this
to your car-care professional.
Thank you. Please give this
Hey, Sky.
Oh, my God. Ted.
What are you...?
Someone from the office, uh,
said you worked down here.
So I thought I'd come down
and say hi.
Wow. Well,
hello.
[TED LAUGHS]
You look great.
No. No, I don't.
I-- I probably just
look crazed.
Not at all.
You look happy.
Last time I saw you...
Hi, there.
Um, I guess, Skyler,
I'm gonna need
to talk to you.
[WHISPERING]
Ted, I really don't think
we have anything
to talk about.
Actually, we do.
SKYLER:
An audit?
Wait, an audit
tomorrow?
How long have you
had this?
Um, a while.
I debated, you know,
contacting you.
Contact me?
What about a lawyer, Ted?
Ted, this is...
This is the CID.
The criminal division.
My God, you're facing
a felony charge here.
A $100,000 fine on top
of the taxes you already owe,
plus five years
in prison.
Yeah. It's bad.
Yeah, it most certainly is.
Look, here's the thing.
I was wondering, maybe,
if, um...
there's some way
you could help with this.
Help?
Help how?
Well, with your knowledge
of how the books
got the way they are,
maybe there's some way
you could undo
what's in there.
You want me to uncook
your books?
Well, maybe there's some method
or some accounting trick
you could,
you know, use--
Ted, it doesn't work
like that.
The damage is already...
My name.
My signatures
are all over those books.
Skyler, I'm accountable,
not you.
Let me explain what's
gonna happen here, okay?
Once the CID sees this
is willful tax fraud,
they are going to build
the strongest possible case.
And once they start
down that path,
they have an 80 percent
conviction rate.
That's because they're allowed
to monitor your mail
and tap your phones.
And not just you, Ted,
everyone involved
in those books.
I can't have this
in my life.
I cannot be audited.
Skyler, you're going to be fine,
okay? They're after me.
It's the captain they want,
not some cashier at a car wash.
No offense.
I'm sorry. I, uh...
Look, I don't want you
to worry, okay?
I'm going to figure out a way
through this, somehow. Okay?
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
Here.
JESSE:
So is he gonna kill him?
Is who gonna kill who?
Gus.
Is he gonna kill Mr. White's
brother-in-law?
I mean, he's the reason
for all of this here, right?
Because it's totally logical
for him to off the dude.
A-hole DEA agent
poking around your junk.
Who needs that, right?
Makes sense to get rid of him
for good.
[WATER SLOSHING]
But killing a cop,
I don't know.
It could look suspicious
if the dude investigating you
suddenly up and dies.
Then there's--
There's Mr. White,
who would be
even more apeshit
if he had family
getting murdered.
He'd never cook
for Gus again.
Guess there's a lot of angles
to consider.
If something were to happen,
would you have a problem?
Who really cares
what I think?
[GUNSHOT]
MAN:
Get down, get down!
[GUNSHOT]
[♪♪♪]
[GUNSHOTS]
Son of a bitch.
You get comfortable, kid.
We may be here a while.
Hey.
Get down!
[♪♪♪]
[GUNFIRE]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Sí.
[IN SPANISH]
Tell them
the answer is "yes."
[LIQUID SLOSHING]
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
[IN ENGLISH]
Should I even ask?
I wouldn't.
So, what, is this going to be
a regular thing now?
Meth cooking
and corpse disposal? Jesus.
Just grab us
a spare barrel, Walter.
What was it this time?
What did this poor bastard do
to piss off Gus?
Or did Gus just need
to send another message?
Shut your mouth.
You shut your mouth,
or I'll shut it for you.
I don't want you talking to me
or Jesse. Just get the barrel.
And if you ever plan
on calling the cops
on one of my guys again,
you go ahead and get
two barrels.
[MACHINERY WHIRRING
DISTANTLY]
Yo. Like, um...
I guess I never thanked you
for what you did.
Thanks.
Next time don't stand there
like an idiot.
Move your feet.
Running and so forth.
But seriously, what--?
What was the deal
with Gus?
The deal?
That Terminator shit.
Walking right into the bullets.
What the hell
was he doing?
The cartel needs Gus.
His distribution network.
They're not looking to kill him.
But, what? The rest of us
are like open season?
Is he doing anything
about that,
or do we keep hanging out
for target practice?
Kid, enough.
You got questions,
ask him yourself.
IRS AGENT:
And here again.
Unreported income.
That's more than a year straight
so far.
Do you want
to say something?
Because I'm having a hard time
figuring it out.
I'd have to, um,
have a look at the copies
of the receipts
to refresh my memory.
Take all the time you need,
Mr. Beneke.
That's why we're here.
[DOOR OPENS]
Oh, I am so sorry
I am late.
I got lost. Hey, Ted.
Sky.
Mwah.
Whoo! This building
is so confusing.
There are doors
everywhere.
Hi. You are...?
Special Agent
James Bekaris.
Ooh, "special."
Skyler White.
Ms. White, you are
the accountant of record
for many of these reports,
correct?
Guilty as charged.
Perhaps
you can you shed light
on this history
of missing revenue?
Missing?
Mm-hm.
No, it's there.
No. Revenue most definitely
flowed through this company,
but it's not all
accounted for in your reports.
Huh!
Let's take a look.
Hm...
Oh, well, you know,
this account here,
that is Mr. Keller's
account.
And Mr. Keller is an old friend
of Ted's dad.
And he always sends
an electronic payment,
which personally I hate,
because I'm a paper person.
But Mr. Keller is one of those
environmental people.
So anyway, since there wasn't
a physical check,
I didn't enter it into the book.
But the money is there.
Ms. White, you've read
Section 61 of the IRC?
I did not follow
what you just said.
How gross income
for a business is defined.
You're not allowed
to do that.
Well, I think I am.
No, you're not.
You know what they say
about opinions.
Everyone's got one.
[LAUGHS]
But seriously, I am.
Doesn't matter
if it's an electronic check
or a paper check,
income is income.
You're not allowed
to not declare it.
When I input everything
into the Quicken,
nothing flashed red, so that's
gotta mean it's okay, right?
Quicken.
Mm-hm.
You used Quicken to manage books
for a business this size.
I did. Oh, do you guys
use that here?
Because it is the best.
It's like having a calculator
on your computer. Amazing.
How did you
get this job?
Oh, Ted hired me.
No, I mean
your qualifications.
What are your qualifications?
Where did you get your training?
Ooh, well, I haven't had
any training, per se.
I've always been naturally good
with numbers.
Got a good instinct for them.
Right, Teddy?
[SIGHS]
Right.
This is all falling
into place now.
Ms. White,
I just have to ask.
You're not managing accounts
anywhere else, are you?
Right now? No.
I'm a cashier at a car wash.
TED:
I'm not, uh, really clear
about what happened in there.
What happened
was good news.
Ignorance of the law doesn't
equate to criminality.
It equates to ignorance.
Look, pay your back taxes,
pay the penalties,
and move on from this.
Just put it behind you.
Ha! Pay with what?
I owe them $617,000.
What am I--?
Look, just figure it out,
all right?
And you've just
dodged prison.
Sell your assets.
Get rid of the BMW,
take out
a second mortgage--
Second mortgage?
I have a lien on my house.
I don't have any assets.
There are no assets
left to sell.
Ted, if you don't
pay them,
they will reopen
the investigation,
and that little fiction
I just spun up there
is gonna
completely unravel.
You have to settle.
Wish I could.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
GUS:
Come in.
I hope you brought
an appetite.
Yeah, I guess.
Mike mentioned
you have some questions.
JESSE:
Yeah.
GUS:
We'll eat first,
and then we'll talk.
Right on.
What am I doing here?
I know you have
concerns.
What happened yesterday
to my man at the farm,
it was a terrible thing.
Oh, the dude getting his head
blown off? Yeah.
I have invited you
into my home,
prepared food
so we could sit and talk.
Discuss what's going on
in this business,
our business, like men.
And I will explain everything
that is happening.
I will answer
your questions.
But first,
I need you to answer
one question for me.
Can you cook
Walter's formula?
What?
Walter's formula.
Can you produce his product
without any help? Alone.
No.
Why?
You're asking me if I can cook
Mr. White's crystal?
Without him?
Me?
The junkie loser
you were about to waste
and dump in the desert
a month ago?
This your plan? Huh?
Invite me in your house,
make whatever this is...
be my buddy, and make me
feel important.
Then get me to keep cooking
for you
after you kill Mr. White?
You wanna--
You wanna talk like men?
Let's talk like men.
You kill Mr. White, you're gonna
have to kill me too.
That is not
what I asked you.
You are here because
circumstances
with the cartel
are untenable.
And I need your help.
I need you to help prevent
an all-out war.
Now, if you would...
answer the question.
[BEEPS]
Hey, you, uh--
You headed out?
Yeah.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
JESSE [OVER ANSWERING MACHINE]:
Yo, Mr. White.
I really gotta talk to you.
I don't know if you're
with your family,
but this is important.
So I'm hoping
you could come over.
Thank God.
Come on in.
You, uh-- You want a beer
or something?
No.
Should I sit down?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sorry, go ahead.
Okay, so, um...
Okay, so word has come down
that they--
They want me
to go to Mexico.
There's some--
Some sort of war brewing
between Gus
and the cartel.
"Word has come down"?
Yeah, the cartel
has been--
Has been messing
with Gus' operation.
Like jacking trucks to,
like, send a message.
And, you know, yesterday,
that dude we brought to the lab.
I mean, they shot him
right in front of me.
I mean, just
blew his head open.
I mean, some sniper nailed him
from like a mile away.
Anyway, uh, they've been
holding them off.
But between the cartel
taking potshots
and your brother-in-law
trying to throw a net
over the whole deal,
it's like what you call
a rock-and-a-hard-place
situation.
So, Gus is gonna cave.
So the cartel wants half
of Gus' entire operation,
and they want
your formula.
And he's gonna
give it to them.
Well, I-- I gotta
I mean, I'm supposed
to go to Mexico and--
And teach a bunch
of cartel chemists
how to cook
a batch of blue.
You know,
and Gus doesn't trust you,
so I gotta go.
I mean,
you're the chemist, man.
You know, not-- Not me.
I mean, let's say I go down to--
You know, go over there-- Go--
Go to the jungle or whatever,
you know, and they got
like actual chemists,
like cartel chemists
asking me chemistry stuff
that I don't know how
to answer because I'm not you.
And what if, like,
all the equipment
is in Mexican
instead of English?
You know? Oh!
I don't know.
I mean, if--
If I mess this up,
I am dead, you know?
All of us.
Mr. White, look,
I-- I need--
I need your help.
Okay, maybe you could--
Maybe you could, like, coach me
or something, you know.
Or you can, like,
give me some notes.
Mr. White?
So you saw Gus?
What? No.
You didn't see Gus.
No.
Then who told you
all of that?
It was-- It was passed down,
like I said.
"Passed down." By whom?
By, uh--
By Mike and them.
I mean, they did. They--
So "they"
doesn't include Gus.
You haven't been with Gus.
You haven't seen Gus.
You haven't spoken to Gus.
Why are you--?
You weren't at Gus' house
last night.
What?
What the hell? Jesus.
Still here.
It's still here.
Jesus.
You look me in the eye
and you tell me
that you weren't at his house
last night.
I, um...
Look, I didn't have a chance,
all right?
Okay? I knew you would
react this way.
I knew you would freak out
and wouldn't believe me.
That's-- That's why I didn't
say anything.
Look, there was just this one
big pot of stew, okay?
He just made this one big pot
and we both ate from it.
What was I supposed to do, huh?
Poison myself?
Two hours and 18 minutes,
and you couldn't figure out
a way to give it to him?
He never left the room.
You lying little shit!
You had one thing to do,
one thing.
That is the only thing,
I might add,
that would save our lives.
And you were right there.
You were in his house.
And you didn't have
the guts to do it.
Two hours and 18 minutes?
You never had any intention
of killing him, did you?
How did you know
I was at his house last night?
Were you following me?
This.
This is how I knew.
You bugged my car?
7:10 to 9:28 p.m.
Two hours and 18 minutes.
But you had no intentions,
did you?
Not the slightest
intention.
Everything that I have
done for you...
Oh!
You put a bug on my car?
I'm sorry, after everything
you've done for me?
What you've done for me?
You killed me,
is what you've done!
You've signed
my death warrant!
And now you want advice?
I'll give you advice:
Go to Mexico and screw up
like I know you will,
and wind up in a barrel
somewhere!
[GRUNTS]
[EYEGLASSES CLATTERING]
[GASPING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[YELLS]
You son of a--
[BOTH YELLING]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[BOTH GASPING AND PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
Can you walk?
Yeah.
Then get the fuck out of here
and never come back.
[PANTING]
[WALT GROANS]
[♪♪♪]