[AIRPLANE APPROACHES]
[♪♪]
You can do this.
[PHONE RINGING]
WALT [ON MACHINE]:
You have reached Walter White.
State your name,
number, and the reason
for your call. Thank you.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
SKYLER:
Third try.
Walt, if you're there,
please pick up.
Okay, well, I really wanted
to do this together,
but I can hear him getting up.
It's not like I can keep him
from seeing the thing.
So, I'm sorry, but I've waited
as long as possible and I...
I guess I'm gonna have
to go ahead without you.
So call me.
Oh, hey.
Happy birthday,
sweet 16.
Mwah!
Thanks, Mom.
I thought you might
sleep through it.
Ha, ha.
So since it's almost,
oh, noon,
I think your first big birthday
decision is breakfast or lunch?
Um, pancakes?
Pancakes it is.
Oh, could you
do me a favor?
I forgot to get the paper.
Can you grab it for me?
Sure.
Thanks.
[DOOR OPENS]
SKYLER:
Surprise.
It's from me and your dad.
Pretty slick, huh?
Yeah. Thanks, Mom.
It's... It's great.
You know, I really did
a lot of research,
and, I don't know, this car
just really stood out to me.
It's got a ton
of great features,
power everything,
solid engine.
It's really roomy so you can
carpool with all your friends.
And, of course, it is safe,
because I'm still your mother.
Oh, and it has a CD player,
so you can listen to tunes
while cruising around.
So you know what?
Breakfast can wait.
You wanna take it
for a spin?
Um, maybe later.
I'm kind of starving.
Yeah, okay.
Well, let's...
Let's get those
pancakes going.
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
SECRETARY:
Saul, he's here.
Bad idea. This is a bad idea.
[INTERCOM BEEPS]
Saul?
Send him in.
Mr. Beneke. Saul Goodman.
Thank you for coming down.
Hey. Yeah, hi.
Have a seat, please.
I, uh...
I don't understand
why I'm here.
Something to do
with my creditors?
Creditors? No.
Uh...
I'll cut right to the chase,
Mr. Beneke. I have bad news.
Uh, nothing but lately.
Your great-aunt Birgit
passed away.
I'm sorry, who?
Uh...
Apparently she passed away
in Diekirch, Luxembourg.
And this was--
Wow, eight years ago.
I just assumed you two were
close, given that...
Well, maybe this is good news.
Birgit left behind
a sizable estate
of which you, Mr. Beneke,
are the primary beneficiary.
What?
She had no immediate relatives,
so the estate's
just been sitting
while the folks over in the EU
searched for a living heir.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Well, I don't know of
any relatives in Luxembourg.
Definitely no one
who would name me in their will.
Huh.
Well...
Well, here we go.
She left no will.
So that's probably why
it took so long.
They traced the inheritance
to your father.
But his having passed--
My condolences.
--you are the next in line
to the tune of $621,552.33.
Wow.
[♪♪]
[IN SPANISH]
And when does Don Eladio arrive?
Let's see how the cook
goes first.
[IN SPANISH]
Who's the chemist?
Is this a joke?
[IN ENGLISH]
He's asking
if you're the chemist.
I'm one of them.
[IN SPANISH]
Okay, we've all met.
Let's get to work.
[IN ENGLISH]
Where's the phenylacetic acid?
[IN SPANISH]
Please show him
the phenylacetic acid.
[IN SPANISH]
We synthesize it ourselves.
All the ingredients are here.
[IN ENGLISH]
They synthesize their own.
What?
I don't do that.
[IN SPANISH]
What's the problem?
[IN ENGLISH]
Look, I get
my phenylacetic acid
from the barrel
with the bee on it.
That's how I know
how to do it.
[IN SPANISH]
Mr. Pinkman
was under the impression
that the phenylacetic acid
would already be synthesized.
Any sophomore chemistry
student can make it.
What kind of amateur
have you brought us?
[IN ENGLISH] What's he saying?
We're working it out.
[IN SPANISH
This is ridiculous.
I'm not letting some infant
who can't even synthesize
phenylacetic acid
teach me my business.
[IN ENGLISH]
Tell this asshole
if he wants to learn
how to make my product,
he's gotta do it my way.
The right way.
[IN ENGLISH]
I speak English.
So you understand
what "asshole" means.
Now, go get me
my phenylacetic acid, asshole.
How long is it gonna take
to get him what he needs?
I don't know. I have no idea.
Several hours, at least.
I can wait.
Gives us time to talk
about the state of this lab.
Don't you have standards?
I mean, this place
is disgusting.
We're gonna scour every vat,
every tank, every cook surface.
We clean up every possible
source of contamination.
And then we cook.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Who do you think you are?
I'm the guy your boss brought
here to show you how it's done.
And if this is how
you run your lab, no wonder.
You're lucky
he hasn't fired your ass.
Now, if you don't want that
to happen,
I suggest you stop whining
like a little bitch
and do what I say.
[IN SPANISH]
Clean up!
[MAN SPEAKING SPANISH]
[BUZZER BUZZES]
[BUZZER BUZZING]
[WALT GROANING]
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[GROANING]
WALT [ON MACHINE]:
You have reached Walter White.
Please state your name,
number, and the reason
for your call. Thank you.
WALT JR.:
Dad, you there?
I'm outside.
Are you okay?
I know you're home.
Your car is here.
You missed my party,
which feels like
something's really wrong.
I'm gonna have to call 911.
I don't know what else to do.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Dad?
WALT:
Uh...
Come in, if you're coming in.
What happened to you?
WALT JR.:
What happened?
[WALT SIGHS]
I got into a fight.
What do you mean, a fight?
Like--? What fight?
Are you gonna
talk to me here?
What are you doing?
I'm calling Mom.
Don't do that.
Look, I...
I appreciate that
you're concerned, but I'm fine.
Just do not call your mother.
Why not?
Because...
I was gambling.
If you tell your mother,
I just--
I will never, never
hear the end of it.
So please.
Can we just keep this
between us?
Would you do that for me?
Just...
Just keep it
to yourself.
I don't understand.
How'd you get into a fight?
And with who?
[SOBBING]
I made a mistake.
It's my own fault.
I had it coming.
Dad...
it's okay.
It-- It's all my fault.
I just...
I'm sorry.
Dad.
Come here.
Come on. Dad, it's okay.
No. Hey, hey, no.
It's okay.
Come on, please. It's okay.
No.
Look at me. Look at me.
[SNIFFLING]
It's okay. It is. Come on.
Come on.
It's-- It's okay.
Hey.
How was your birthday?
Good. Get some rest.
Okay.
The new car?
Did you drive it here?
Yeah.
WALT:
That's good.
You like it?
Uh...
Sure. I do.
It drives great.
That's good, Jesse.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
Ugh! Yes. Yes.
Well done.
The first of many.
Yeah? What's that mean?
You're staying.
You belong to the cartel now.
SKYLER:
You can't come
to my work like this.
You're too recognizable.
Your face is plastered on every
bus bench in a five-mile radius.
Celebrities have to get cars
washed like everybody else.
I wouldn't have come
if it wasn't important.
What is it?
I went ahead and met
with your Mr. Beneke. Right?
Which, I will say again, loudly
and for the record, bad idea.
Yes, but it is better
than prison, correct?
Marginally. Which is why
I disbursed the funds.
All right, good.
Yeah. I can't believe
he actually bought it.
Great-aunt Birgit. What?
But you called it. People see
zeroes dance before their eyes,
it's like highway hypnosis.
So, what's the problem?
You and I don't wear
the same rose-colored glasses
where Johnny Fabulous
is concerned.
So I kept an eye
on his bank accounts
and pulled
his credit report.
If you would,
note the time on that.
Three fifty-four p.m.
yesterday.
Three hours
after leaving my office.
He bought
a Mercedes SL550.
He's actually leasing it,
but he put 4500 down.
He's gonna pay 1830 a month.
Fully loaded. He even got
the heated steering wheel.
But that's upwards of 6300
that won't be going to the IRS.
I just thought
you might like to know,
loath as I am to say,
I told you so.
Where is he now?
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
Hey.
How you doing?
Good.
Um, how are you?
I'm fine, but your mother
is going to be worried sick.
I called her last night.
Oh, God.
I told her I was
spending the night at Louis'.
It's cool. So...
Uh, how are you?
[SIGHS]
I'm fine, son. I...
I...
Well, I...
I took these painkillers that
I had left over from my surgery,
and I made
the brilliant decision
to wash them down
with a couple of beers.
Not my most sterling moment,
I admit, but...
I'm fine.
I wish I could take back
last night.
It was your birthday.
This shouldn't be on your mind.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
I'm your father,
and I don't want
last night to be...
I mean, you really...
can't think of me like...
Like what?
I-- I don't understand.
My father died when I was 6.
You knew that, right?
Yeah.
He had Huntington's disease.
It's...
It destroys
portions of the brain,
affects muscle control,
leads to dementia,
it's just a nasty disease.
It's genetic.
Terrified my mother
that I might have it,
so they ran tests on me
when I was a kid,
but I came up clean.
My father fell very ill
when I was...
four or 5.
He spent a lot of time
in the hospital.
My...
[LAUGHS]
My mother would tell me
so many stories about my father.
She would talk about him
all the time.
I knew about his personality,
how he treated people.
I even knew
how he liked his steaks cooked.
Medium rare.
Just like you.
I knew things about my father.
I had a lot of information.
It's because people
would tell me these things.
They would paint this picture
of my father for me.
And I always pretended
that was who I saw too.
Who I remembered.
But it was a lie.
In truth, I only have one real
actual memory of my father.
It must have been
right before he died.
My mother would take me
to the hospital to visit him.
And I remember the smell
in there, the chemicals.
It was as if they used up
every single cleaning product
they could find
in a 50-mile radius.
Like they didn't want you
smelling the sick people.
There was this stench
of Lysol and bleach.
I mean, you could just feel it
coating your lungs.
Anyway, there lying on the bed
is my father.
He's all...
He's all twisted up.
And my mom, she...
puts me on her lap.
She's sitting on the bed
next to him
so I can get
a good look at him.
But really, he just scares me.
And he's looking
right at me,
but I can't even be sure
that he knows who I am.
And your grandmother
is talking,
trying to be cheerful,
you know, as she does,
but the only thing
I could remember
is him breathing.
Ah. This...
This rattling sound.
Like if you were shaking
an empty spray paint can.
Like there was nothing in him.
Anyway...
that is the only real memory
that I have of my father.
I don't want you to think of me
the way I was
last night.
I don't want that
to be the memory
you have of me when I'm gone.
Remembering you
that way...
wouldn't be so bad.
The bad way to remember you
would be the way...
The way you've been
this whole last year.
At least last night
you were...
You were real, you know?
Bye.
Somewhere you should be?
Well, basically
it was a temporary hiatus.
Give us two weeks, we will
be up and running 100 percent.
All right, talk to your people
and get back to me, okay?
Hi.
Yeah, thanks, Tanya.
Okay. You bet.
Say hi to the kids for me.
Hey.
Hi.
Nice surprise. What's up?
Just thought I'd swing by,
see how things are going.
Well, things are...
Things took a turn.
It's kind of crazy.
Oh, yeah?
The universe is telling me
something. I got good news.
Some very good news,
and, um...
I'm getting the business
going again.
Wow.
I figure
we haven't been down long,
so we should be able to get
most of our contracts back. Sit.
Oh, thank you.
That's--
Um, gosh, that's...
That's-- Wow.
How is that even possible?
Well, I got a very
unexpected...
cash infusion.
Huh.
I guess someone's
looking out for me.
I guess so.
Um, is that yours, outside?
Oh. Yeah, well, you know,
I can't be driving
a piece of crap.
You gotta present
that successful image.
Right. So the IRS stuff.
That's resolved?
Yeah, it's in progress.
So you paid them?
Well, not yet, but I will.
When?
Well, it's not that simple.
Here's the thing: I never had
proper legal counsel.
So I was thinking
I should hire someone good
who can maybe
hammer out a better deal.
There will never be
a better deal, Ted.
The deal is
you pay your back taxes,
you pay your penalty,
and you don't go to prison.
That's a good deal.
So...
Let's keep our priorities
straight.
Well, my priority
is getting my business back.
Putting my employees
on the payroll,
so they can pay
their mortgages.
Right. But I think
your employees would agree
you need to get your
financial situation in control
before you can help them.
Boy, the IRS
got you on commission?
I'm just saying that,
though I really understand
the temptation
to restart the business,
maybe the universe
is telling you
that you need to pay
what you owe.
Skyler, um,
this is my money.
Why are we having
this conversation?
You're no longer
a part of my life.
A decision you made,
by the way.
So I don't understand why
you're hectoring me about this.
Ted, this affects both of us.
No, it doesn't.
I'm telling you
to drop this.
You need to use that money
to pay your bill.
By the end of this month.
Which you promised the IRS
in writing that you would do.
It is that simple.
Okay.
Okay, duly noted.
What does that mean?
Does that mean yes? Because
I really need a yes here, Ted.
All right, Skyler,
I'll tell you what it means.
It means, in the most
respectful way possible,
there's the door,
and I'm inviting you to...
And thank you for your concern,
but I'm done talking.
From whom exactly do you think
you got that 600,000, Ted?
Great-aunt Birgit?
That was you?
Yeah.
What is this shit?
I don't get a vote?
I'm supposed to just
stay down here forever?
I promise you this:
Either we're all going home
or none of us are.
Now settle down.
On your feet.
[SIGHS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Gustavo.
[IN SPANISH]
I'm so happy
you finally
came to your senses.
[IN SPANISH]
May I present the cook.
[IN ENGLISH]
This is your new employer.
You address him as Don Eladio.
It's a term of respect.
[IN SPANISH]
Hello, young man.
He doesn't speak Spanish?
No.
[IN SPANISH]
And he's no chemist,
I'll tell you that.
I don't care
if he's a pig farmer.
He cooks better meth
than you do
with all your fancy
college degrees.
And this one will have
plenty of time to learn Spanish.
Sí.
What's in there?
A gift?
Gustavo,
you're so generous.
[IN SPANISH]
It's a token of respect.
In honor
of our renewed friendship.
Mm.
Let's see what's in here.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
No, impossible!
[WHISTLES]
Zafiro Añejo!
Look at this. Even the bottle
is a work of art.
It's perfection!
Perhaps...
it's too good to share.
What do you think, Gustavo?
It's yours to do with
as you choose.
Aha. Sí.
I choose to drink it!
[LAUGHS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Careful.
That's beautiful stuff.
If you spill a drop,
I'll cut off your hand.
Come on, hurry up.
Gustavo.
[IN ENGLISH]
Welcome to Mexico.
Now you say:
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
GUS [IN SPANISH]:
This one's an addict.
To work, he must be sober.
[IN SPANISH]
None for you!
[LAUGHS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MEN SPEAKING SPANISH]
ELADIO:
Ah. Ugh!
Enough business!
Bring the girls!
[MEN CHATTERING
IN SPANISH]
[DANCE MUSIC IN SPANISH
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[MEN SINGING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[IN ENGLISH]
No. No, no, I don't...
[MAN RAPPING IN ENGLISH
INDISTINCTLY]
[IN SPANISH]
Gustavo. Cheer up, man.
Gustavo, I'm not angry.
I had to spank you.
But what choice did I have?
Look, once every 20 years,
you forget your place.
There's no place
for emotion in this.
You of all people
should understand.
Business is business.
[IN SPANISH]
If you'll excuse me.
Where are you going?
To use your bathroom.
If I may.
Miguel!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Show Gustavo the pisser.
And make sure
he doesn't get lost.
Hurry up.
[VOMITS]
[DANCE MUSIC IN SPANISH
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[IN ENGLISH]
What the--?
[GAGGING]
[GUESTS CHATTERING
IN SPANISH]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[♪♪]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Make yourself useful.
Find a gun.
[GRUNTING]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[IN SPANISH]
Don Eladio is dead!
His capos are dead!
You have no one left
to fight for!
Fill your pockets
and leave in peace!
Or fight me
and die!
[IN ENGLISH]
I hope to hell that works.
Take him.
[GRUNTING]
[CHATTERING IN SPANISH]
[♪♪]
Keys.
No. No.
Okay. Okay.
Hey. Hey, you still with us?
Go.
[GUNSHOTS]
[PANTING]
Kid. Get us out of here, kid.
[GRUNTS]
JESSE:
Come on.
[MIKE GRUNTING]
[♪♪]