[PEOPLE CHATTERING IN SPANISH]
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[HONKING CONTINUES]
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
JESSE:
In here.
[♪♪♪]
[DOCTOR AND STAFF
SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What about him?
[EKG BEEPING]
[GRUNTS]
JESSE:
Hey. Someone.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Help. Ugh. Assistance.
This man needs help.
This man pays my salary.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTS]
[SCALE BEEPS]
[SCALE BEEPING]
Forty-point-two-three pounds.
Are they back yet?
Have you heard from anyone?
If Pinkman is gone,
I'm done.
Do you understand? I quit.
I just told you,
40.23 pounds.
[SCALE BEEPING]
Forty-point-two-one.
[BOX THUDS]
My brother-in-law,
he keeps talking about
driving out to the factory farm.
And I have-- I have stalled him
as long as I possibly can.
It's really
at the point now
where he's gonna find someone
else to take him there.
So I don't know if it's
been made presentable yet.
But I should be the one
to take him out there, right?
Can you just run it up
the chain of command then?
[BUTTON CLICKS]
WALT:
Anything suspicious?
Still no, Walt.
[LAUGHS]
Well, then should we go?
Got some place to be?
Because it's, like,
the third time
you asked me that.
No, I'm just curious
what the next move is.
Our next three moves
is sitting here and waiting.
This here's the job, buddy.
Ain't all supermodels
and speedboats, you know.
Any, uh, cartel news
these days?
Seems like I'm always reading
something or other in the paper.
Yeah, well,
not a lot happening stateside.
Hearing rumblings
about some big play down south.
Lots of bodies,
apparently. Tsk.
You know, even by
cartel standards.
We'll know more when
the buzzards leave the bones.
[HANK SIGHS]
So when we gonna talk
about your face?
[SIGHS]
I don't wanna get into it, okay?
No, it's not okay.
My brother-in-law shows up
looking like Macho Camacho,
and he thinks
we're not gonna discuss it?
If you're in over your head
on something,
don't you think I might be
the guy to come to?
You know,
one of my old, uh,
buddies from Glynco
had a gambling problem,
except his thing was scratch
cards instead of blackjack.
[CHUCKLES]
Dumb Okie bastard
had his car repo'd playing
scratch-and-wins.
[LAUGHS]
He's fine now, you know.
He got help and all.
But I know he got on a ride
that was rough to get off of.
I'm just saying I'm here,
you know.
If you want to talk about it.
I don't want to talk about it,
to you or to anyone else.
I'm done explaining myself.
[EKG BEEPING]
Hey, uh... Yo, you think
he needs more blood?
It's in the refrigerator.
What, you--?
You want me to, uh...?
DOCTOR:
A-negative, yes?
Your blood type?
Um...
I don't know, maybe.
[LAUGHS]
A-negative, 25 years old,
seventy kilo, 180 centimeters.
You smoke, you drink,
you, uh, puff, puff, puff.
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
But no disease, no condition.
No complication
other than an allergy to...
Oh, wait, don't say.
Erythromycin.
But I have cefazolin here,
so no problem.
How do you know all that?
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Jesus.
He thought of everything.
O-negative.
That's what he needs.
It's time to go.
What about Mike?
With this injury? No travel.
At least a week.
I'll send for him.
[IN SPANISH]
You need protection, Gustavo?
[CHUCKLES]
I wouldn't have guessed.
[DOCTOR CHUCKLES
THEN GUS GROANS]
[BOTH SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[IN ENGLISH]
Water and rest.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
[GUS SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
JESSE:
What happened to the plane?
There are many
good ways south.
But, unfortunately,
only one way north.
Six miles to Texas.
I've got a man there
who'll drive us
the rest of the way.
I kind of liked the plane.
So you gonna make it?
Six miles is pretty far.
I'll make it.
You did well down here.
And you also
proved a point.
I think you can run the lab
by yourself now.
Don't you?
Let Mr. White go.
Pay him off or fire him.
Don't kill him.
You know that won't work.
Then you got a problem.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hi. We're home.
Are you doing your homework?
WALT JR.:
Yeah.
Mm-hm. Well,
dinner is in about 30.
[SIGHS]
[MACHINE BEEPS]
TED [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, sorry to call you at home,
but I think maybe
you're not getting my messages.
That or you just
don't feel like talking to me.
[LOWERS VOLUME]
Anyway, why I've been calling
is because that thing
we discussed?
Well, I've been thinking,
and, uh,
I decided I can't do it.
That's probably not
what you wanted to hear.
But hopefully you'll
understand,
and if you want to talk
more about it, that's fine.
So call me. I'm around.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hey. Come on in.
Hi.
Ahem. First, I wanna
tell you that I get it.
From what you've told me,
this situation with Walt's
gambling sounds...
intense.
Yeah, it definitely was.
And continues to be.
So I would greatly appreciate it
if you would just...
help me out here.
Well, I've thought
long and hard about this...
and, uh, here's
what I want to do. Ahem.
So is, uh,
Walt gonna be okay?
Are you in contact with him?
Um, he's fine.
Good. That's good.
He doesn't know about you
offering--?
No. Absolutely not.
And I mean to keep it
that way, so...
Six hundred and seventeen
thousand dollars
written out to me.
Uh... What is this?
I can't take your money.
Oh?
And why is that?
Because, at the end of the day,
paying my debt with illicit
gambling winnings, uh...
I don't know,
it feels wrong.
"It feels wrong"?
To me it does.
Uh-huh.
I'm not judging
you or Walt.
I'm just saying
I feel uncomfortable with it.
Well, um, Ted,
the whole reason
we're in this mess
is because you had me
cooking your books.
So when did wrong suddenly
become a problem for you?
Now, hold on,
that was a one-time measure
in an honest attempt
to protect my employees
and save my dad's company.
It might've been a mistake,
but that's no reason
to go out and make another.
No, Ted, this is the big
mistake, right here.
You owe the federal government
$617,000.
If you do not pay them,
they will come after you
and then they
will come after me.
And if they
audit my business,
find out that
Walt and I paid for it
with close to a million dollars
in untaxed gambling winnings,
we will go to prison,
where you will already be.
Do you understand?
I understand you're upset,
but I think
you're overstating things too.
No one's going to prison.
Oh, my God. How are you
not following me here?
Okay, fine,
let's say I take your advice.
I pay the IRS. Then what?
Then you don't owe them.
Okay, but I still owe
the bank, Skyler.
I'm still
going to go bankrupt
and lose my business
and my home.
I still have to pull my girls
out of school.
Just because I pay
some stupid fine
doesn't make
my life any less ruined.
So if I'm understanding you
correctly,
you're saying you can't take
the money I gave you...
but you can take a larger
amount.
No. I'm just saying,
as much as I appreciate
the gesture,
the money you gave me
doesn't really change anything.
Because it's not enough?
No, no, don't twist my words.
This isn't about amounts,
this is about
me doing the right thing.
Ted, are you blackmailing me?
What? No. Blackmailing?
God.
I feel I'm not
explaining things right.
I think you're
explaining it fine.
I notice that, uh,
this is for less than
what I gave you, by the way.
That's the Mercedes.
I leased it
before I knew
where the money came from.
Mm. Now that you know,
you will be returning it.
The leases are ironclad,
so I have to see
what's possible,
but, yeah,
I'm gonna do my best.
And I will pay you back
as soon as I can.
I don't want you to pay me, Ted.
I want you to pay them.
Try it again.
Write a new check.
Skyler.
Same amount.
This time, made payable--
What happened to us?
Make it payable to
the Internal Revenue Service.
I can't.
You have to.
Actually, no I don't.
Write it.
[SLAMS DOOR]
Saul Goodman, please.
Tell him it's important.
Yeah.
What have I done?
[TRAIN HORN TOOTS ON TV]
[EXPLOSION ON TV]
[CHATTERING]
GUS:
Hello, Hector.
[TRAIN HORN TOOTING ON TV]
[EXPLOSION ON TV]
All of them, Hector.
Don Eladio.
Don Paco. Cesar.
Renaldo. Artuno.
Cisco and Luis.
Escalada.
All dead.
As is your grandson,
Joaquin.
Do you know
who killed Joaquin?
Would you like to see?
This young man.
Do you remember him?
That young man
shot Joaquin to death...
while I made my escape.
I believe you have
met him before.
It was just
you and Joaquin.
He was the only family
you had left.
Now the Salamanca name
dies with you.
Will you look at me now?
[MILITARY MARCH MUSIC
PLAYING ON TV]
Look at me, Hector.
Look at me.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CROWD CHATTERING
LOUDLY ON TV]
[HORN HONKS]
I really appreciate
you doing this.
You guys must have
your hands filled
with the car wash and all.
No, no. No worries.
Happy to do it.
Besides,
it gives me a chance
to see how you work a case.
[LAUGHS]
It's, uh, interesting.
Yeah.
Like watching
weeds grow, huh? Heh.
Ah, this job
can be boring as hell.
Until it's not.
[LAUGHS]
So, um...
Any more news on that thing
in Mexico?
No, same old,
same old.
Bunch of animals clawing
each other's eyes out over turf.
So you think all the victims
were cartel members?
Not in the loop
enough to know.
Take a right on this street,
will you?
Right?
But, uh, we're going
to the chicken farm,
that's straight ahead.
No, we're taking
a little detour.
All right.
Yeah, there's this, uh,
industrial laundry
I wanna check out.
It's not far.
Just, yeah, turn right here.
[♪♪♪]
What, uh--?
What laundry? What about it?
It's owned by this company,
this Madrigal Electromotive.
It's this big German
conglomerate
right into everything.
It turns out
it's the same company
that owns
Fring's chicken joints.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Sounds like a real shot
in the dark there.
I mean,
you said it yourself.
If this Madrigal, is it?
If this is such
a big conglomerate,
then, you know, they must own
all kinds of businesses.
No, it just--
It just sounds kind of thin.
Well, look at you.
You lose your hair,
go on a couple stakeouts,
all of a sudden
you're, what, Kojak?
[SNICKERING]
I'm just saying.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Now, the chicken farm, however,
boy, that place seems ripe
for some kind
of clandestine activities.
I just don't want us to miss
anything, you know?
You wanna talk about
clandestine activities?
Madrigal Electromotive
also owns a subsidiary
that manufactures this
state-of-the-art
air-filtration system.
And none other than
Gale Boetticher
took delivery
of one of these systems.
A chemist who was in possession
of hand-drawn plans
for a meth super-lab
and was visited
by none other than Gus Fring
just days before he was capped
in the face, okay?
This shit is starting
to feel like--
Like Three Days Of The Condor,
you know?
Anyway, an industrial laundry
would be one hell of a place
to hide a meth lab.
There it is right up there.
Just turn in there.
[♪♪♪]
Walt, slow down.
You gotta turn in there, Walt.
What are you doing?
You missed it.
Sorry. It looked like
a dirt road.
I thought
you meant further up.
[SIGHS]
Just-- Just bang
a U-ie over here.
[♪♪♪]
Whoa!
HANK:
Mm. Hits the spot.
Thanks, guys.
[LAUGHING]
I said to Mom
"ice cream," but,
um, she was like:
"It tastes the same
[DOORBELL RINGS]
and it's healthier."
So, heh, sorry.
I tried.
[DOOR OPENS]
Frozen yogurt does taste the
same. Tastes exactly the same.
Wow. I feel, like,
sorry for your taste buds.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Heh-heh. Weigh in here,
Uncle Hank.
Hey, it's free food. Ahem.
Free food always tastes good.
Free drinks even better.
MARIE:
Hey, hon.
Can you handle
another visitor?
HANK:
Ho-ho! Mr. Magoo.
Yeah, sure. Hey, watch out.
Don't run into any walls
or anything.
WALT [LAUGHING]:
Okay.
Hey, Dad.
Hey, son.
So how you feeling, Hank?
It feels like one of those cones
they put on dogs,
so they don't lick
their own balls.
Nice. Thank you.
Stay classy.
Anyway, hanging in there.
Glad you stopped by.
Listen,
I'm sorry about all this.
I mean, that guy
just came out of nowhere.
Yeah, actually, he didn't.
I saw him coming a mile away.
Hey, just mark it down
as a brain fart
and, uh, be thankful
no one got killed.
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
Your Hardy Boys routine is over.
No more asking him
to drive you on stakeouts.
It's too dangerous.
You hear me?
I'll do it.
No, you won't.
No, Marie's right. It was
a bit short-sighted of me.
That's why I, uh, caved.
SKYLER: Caved?
Yeah, I broke down.
I, uh, ordered me a gimp-mobile.
[CHUCKLES]
I wish you would
stop calling it that.
What do you mean?
Like a handi-van with a lift?
No, no, it's a regular Tahoe.
It's got hand controls.
I ordered it.
Should be here in about a week.
I don't expect to be in it long,
but, uh, gotta get around
on my own.
Stop being
such a damn burden to everyone.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Oh.
Oh. Sorry.
Car wash business.
SAUL [OVER PHONE]:
Hey, it's me. Can you talk?
[IN LOW VOICE]
I can listen.
Fair enough.
He doesn't own a gun,
at least not one
that he bought legally.
Nor does
his home security system
have any panic-button
arrangement.
So way I see it,
we're good to go.
If this is still how
you want to handle it.
Like I said,
I don't want anyone hurt.
All I want
is for him to write a check.
Yeah. It's gonna be fine.
I've got my A-team on it.
[HEADSET BEEPS]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Can I help you?
Yeah, thanks.
What--? You just can't--
What's this about?
I'll tell you
what this is about.
This is about you and me doing
our best to keep Huell happy.
Huell? Who's Huell?
This is Huell.
Huell, you happy?
Reasonably.
What would make you unhappy?
This motherfucker
not doing what he's told.
KUBY:
If you were unhappy, Mr. Beneke
wouldn't care for that?
I'm gonna say no.
Well, there you have it.
Let's go find your checkbook.
Ready?
Here we go. All right?
We're walking,
we're swinging our feet.
There you go. Very nice.
Beautiful place you have here.
This way. So the amount's
gonna be for $617,226--
Whoa. I don't have
that kind of money.
Hold that thought.
Forgot to mention we know
exactly how much money
is in your account, okay?
Understand? You still want to
say that stuff from before?
Maybe not.
So $617,226 and 31 cents,
made payable to
the Internal Revenue Service.
What?
Wait, this is, uh...?
Skyler? Skyler White sent you?
It doesn't matter.
For now, all you have to do
is worry about that.
My God, this is a
misunderstanding.
Skyler is a dear friend of mine,
all right?
Let me call her.
We'll, uh...
No, you're misunderstanding,
Mr. Beneke.
Phone-call time is over.
Check-writing time.
Skyler would never
do this to me.
Sit down and write!
There you go.
Six hundred seventeen thousand,
two hundred twenty-six dollars
and thirty-one...
Yeah, right.
You got it.
Huell, you happy?
Ha-ha. Huell's happy.
All right. Everything else
has been filled out for you.
All's we need...
is a signature
right there.
Great.
Hard part is over.
Here's what happens next.
Huell is gonna
hang here with you.
I'm gonna make sure I get this
down to UPS before 5:00.
Way back, I'm gonna
grab some sandwiches.
The three of us can hang out
and play cards or watch TV
for the next couple of days
until the check clears.
Painless, right?
Unless you don't have cable,
in which case
it's gonna suck, so...
[GRUNTING]
Does the laundry
have to be dirty?
Nope.
[♪♪♪]
Someone cooked here.
You've been out of commission
four days.
You think
we're gonna shut down
the whole operation
just for you?
Who cooked? Who was here?
[♪♪♪]
JESSE:
I don't know how you're doing
the flips. Tell me.
BROCK:
Keep cool.
Oh. Oh, I'm gonna get you.
Oh, I'm gonna get you.
[LAUGHS]
JESSE:
Jump.
[JESSE CHUCKLES]
You're pressing buttons, and
it makes you do magical stuff.
No.
Yes. Cheater.
Hey.
Who's winning?
I am.
Well-- Yeah. Look at you.
Look at--
Ooh. Yeah.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
A hundred and one back flips,
I did.
Oh, you.
Hey, keep it going.
Hey, hey, hey.
Relax.
Ooh. You're in trouble.
JESSE: Good luck.
Mama is in the house.
Jesse.
What do you want? I'm busy.
We need to talk.
I got nothing to say to you,
man.
Jesse, please. I'm sorry.
Just one minute.
That's all I ask.
Get the hell out of my house.
Come on. Come on.
Hey. Just give me one minute.
Let me just explain.
Okay.
Let me--
Shh! Shh!
All right. All right. Okay,
okay. All right, I'm sorry.
I know that you have been
cooking without me.
That's right. So what?
So what?
Isn't it obvious to you
what Gus is planning?
He's going to use you
to replace me.
He doesn't think
you need me anymore.
Jesse. Jesse, if you agree
to replace me,
he will kill me.
You brought your
brother-in-law to our lab.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
That's not my fault, Jesse.
Get off.
You've got to help me.
Please.
The last time I asked
for your help, you said:
"I hope you end up buried in a
barrel in the Mexican desert."
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PANTING]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[GRUNTING]
[WALT GASPS]
You are done.
Fired.
Do not show your face
at the laundry again.
Stay away from Pinkman.
Do not go near him.
Ever.
Are you listening to me?
Or else you'll do what?
What did you say?
Stay away from Pinkman...
or else you'll do...
what?
Kill me?
If you could kill me...
I'd already be dead.
But you can't.
You can't kill me,
because Jesse wouldn't
cook for you if you did.
That's it, isn't it?
[WALT CHUCKLES THEN COUGHING]
No matter
how hard you try
to turn him against me,
to screw with his head,
so that
he would hate my guts,
and he still
won't let you do it.
For now.
But he'll come around.
In the meantime, there's the
matter of your brother-in-law.
He is a problem
you promised to resolve.
You have failed.
Now it's left to me
to deal with him.
You can't--
If you try to interfere...
this becomes
a much simpler matter.
I will kill your wife.
I will kill your son.
I will kill
your infant daughter.
[KNIFE CLICKS]
[GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
[COUGHING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[WALT GRUNTING]
[GRUNTING]
Great. Perfect.
You know, this is just...
I told her
you were my A-team.
It was an act of God.
Ain't no accounting
for no act of God.
Check is in the mail,
at least.
"Hello, Mrs. White.
"The good news is the IRS
has been paid off.
The bad news is..."
Ugh! Jesus!
[SIGHS]
Well, here goes nothing.
FRANCESCA: Hey! Hey!
SAUL: Whoa, whoa. Slow down.
What the--?
WALT: Saul.
How did you hear?
What? Hear what?
Guys, go, go, go. Scram.
What the hell happened to you?
Saul. Saul.
This man that
we spoke of before.
This person that you said
could disappear me.
Give me a new life.
Yeah.
Make sure I'm never found.
Yeah, I need him, Saul.
Gus is gonna murder
my whole family.
Christ.
I need this man now.
Saul. Now, Saul!
Yeah, yeah.
There's no coming back.
You're gonna get new Socials,
new identities.
You can't contact your friends
or relatives ever again.
All right. I understand.
How are you gonna sell this
to that wife of yours
and your son?
I have got no choice.
You're wanted by scary
individuals,
not to mention the law.
You're high-risk.
You'll need the deluxe service.
It'll cost you.
WALT:
How much?
Last quote I got on the deluxe
was 125 grand.
But you got four people. It'll
be at least half a million.
He accepts cash only.
I've got the money.
Please!
Here.
Okay.
This is a vacuum cleaner
repair company.
Did you expect
Haji's Quick-Vanish?
I don't even know his name.
You just call
and leave a message.
You tell them
that you need a new dust filter
for a Hoover MaxExtract
Pressure Pro, Model 60.
I wrote it right on there.
He'll call you back.
Okay, fine. How long does
it take for him to arrange?
The guy works fast.
That's the game.
You gotta have your family
packed and ready
before you make the call.
He'll tell you where to meet,
he'll put you up
in a safe house.
You gotta bring money.
He doesn't lift a finger
unless he's paid.
Okay.
Saul.
Can't say it's been a pleasure--
I need you to do
one more thing for me.
You need to call the DEA.
You need to tell them
Gus has a hit out on Hank.
You have to do it for me.
I gotta go on living here.
I'm way too comfortable in my--
Just call anonymously.
You call anonymously!
I can't!
I'm practically
in the DEA family.
I go to their
Christmas parties.
They know me.
They know my voice.
They'll know me.
Please, you gotta do it for me.
Please. Please.
No.
My brother-in-law doesn't
deserve to die because of this.
There's no way
I'm mentioning Gus.
Okay.
The most I'll go--
I'll say it's the cartel.
They're back to finish the job.
You say whatever
you have to say.
You just give me
an hour to...
I need to collect
my wife and kids. Okay?
Give me an hour and then you
make the phone call.
Don't forget. Please.
Yeah.
Thank you, Saul.
[♪♪♪]
[COUGHING]
No, no, no.
Where's the rest?
That's not enough.
SKYLER: Walt?
Down here!
Walt, what did
that phone call mean?
Where is it?
Where's the rest?
The money, Skyler.
Where is the rest?
Skyler, where is the money?
[BOTH PANTING]
[♪♪♪]
I gave it to Ted.
What?
You did what?
Walt, I had to.
For us, for the family.
I swear, Walt--
You gave our money to Beneke?
Walt, please.
Please just hear me out. Please.
[SCREAMS]
[WALT SOBBING]
Walt.
[PHONE RINGING]
[WALT LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY]
Walt.
[PHONE CONTINUES RINGING]
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hi, you've reached the White
family. Please leave a message.
MARIE [OVER SPEAKER]:
Skyler.
It's happening again.
The DEA called, they got some
tip from an informant.
The cartel,
they want to kill Hank.
Oh, God.
They're sending agents to our
house right now to guard us.
Oh, God.
When is this going to end?
[WALT CONTINUES
LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY]
Marie, I'm here.
I'm here.
Tell me exactly what happened.
[COUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
[♪♪♪]