[♪♪♪]
They're here, out front.
SKYLER: How many?
Nelson Brey, three others.
His toothbrush?
Got it.
What about your stuff?
Oh, we'll talk to them
about stopping at your place.
Skyler. Skyler.
What?
I'm not going.
I'm not going
to Hank and Marie's.
We're in danger.
Yes, that's true.
Because of me.
It doesn't matter.
All that matters
is the rest of you are safe.
And that's why
I'm not going with you.
I'm the real target.
But we'll all be safer
at Hank's.
No, no, no.
No one will be safe at Hank's
if I'm there.
Walt, it's the DEA.
Skyler, you don't know
these people.
I--
No. Skyler, please.
Trust me.
This is how it has to be.
Those agents outside.
They're not gonna just
leave you here.
It's protective custody.
All they know
is that Hank is the only
person that's in danger.
They're including us
as a courtesy to Marie,
to keep her happy.
How am I supposed
to explain that
to Marie or Junior?
Or Hank?
I don't know.
But you'll do it.
You'll figure it out.
Hank knows that Marie
will be overreacting.
Except she's not.
I'll talk to Hank. You just
back me up with everyone else.
You really expect me to say,
"Okay, Walt, sure.
Just stay here and..."
No.
There's gotta be
another way.
There isn't.
There was.
But now there isn't.
Walt,
how long till you're safe?
Till you can work this out?
Oh, Skyler.
No.
Skyler.
I have lived under the threat
of death for a year now.
And because of that,
I've made choices.
I--
Listen to me.
I alone should suffer the
consequences of those choices,
no one else.
And those consequences,
they're coming.
No more prolonging
the inevitable.
Feed that belt through
those seatbelt holders.
Hank, I've got
a car wash to run.
I mean,
you don't honestly believe
that I'm in danger,
do you? Me?
Oh, Jesus, it's gonna go over
like a lead balloon.
It'll be Marie that kills me.
Well, just know that I'll
get there as soon as I can.
And let Steve Gomez know.
I told his guys.
And just stay safe.
Oh, please. Whole thing's
just a giant jerk-off.
Yeah, yeah. But keep your head
down anyway, all right?
HANK:
All right.
All right, buddy. Take care.
[HOLLY CRYING]
Shh, shh, shh.
I know.
Okay, sweetie.
Okay, my love.
Okay. Okay.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]
Okay, my darling.
It's okay.
We're all right.
Okay. Shh.
[♪♪♪]
[APOLLO SUNSHINE'S "WE ARE
BORN WHEN WE DIE" PLAYING]
♪ Why ♪
♪ Say goodbye? ♪
♪ We are born again ♪
♪ When we die ♪
♪ But we will never
Leave our lives ♪
[♪♪♪]
WALT JR.:
He's gonna risk his life
over a stupid car wash?
Does he understand
what's going on with Uncle Hank?
He'll come when he's able.
That's pathetic. I--
How hard did you even try
or did you?
Hey, hey, hey.
Lay off your mom.
Well, you know, Hank. We
wouldn't be arguing about this
if you and Steve
would make him come.
Why didn't you put him
in the car?
It's not Nazi Germany,
all right?
Oh, you--
Nazi Germany.
If I had a dollar
for every time I heard that.
I'm gonna call him.
He's gonna get his behind here.
Immediately. End of story.
Thank you, at least
somebody is listening.
Because we are all
in danger here.
We're not
all in danger here.
Will you stop saying that?
That is asking for trouble.
Come on, Walt.
He's not picking up.
Look, could we just take this
down a notch, okay? Everybody?
You guys can stay here
as long as you like.
We got plenty of room.
I wouldn't worry about
any danger to Walt
or any of us, okay?
This whole thing
is just a damn smoke screen.
How do you mean
"a smoke screen"?
HANK:
An anonymous threat against me?
I'm stuck in a wheelchair,
I'm not even on the job.
No, someone didn't like the way
I've been spending my free time.
What? Minerals?
Timing seem a bit
odd to you, huh?
I start looking
into Fring, I'm under lockdown
for my protection.
Did you say--?
Gus Fring?
What--?
From the chicken restaurant?
Hank, what are you
talking about?
Just one man's humble opinion,
that's all.
I think Los Pollos Hermanos
is a front
for the biggest meth distributor
in the Southwest.
MARIE:
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Steve, are you
even looking into this?
GOMEZ:
We're looking into everything.
But we work on fact,
not conjecture.
And the fact is that the
scumbags that hit you first
were Mexican cartel, not some
German multinational whatever.
Definitely not
Colonel Sanders.
Now, if we even had a shred
of proof--
Wasn't that what
you get paid to go get?
From that laundry I told you
about. I'd start there.
Come on, man.
GOMEZ: Jesus.
It's the perfect spot
for a meth superlab.
Oh, my God.
HANK:
Hey,
what if I'm right?
GOMEZ:
Even if you were right--
And you ain't.
--there's no way a judge
is gonna give me a warrant.
Warrant? What happened to good
old-fashioned knock and talk?
Oh, that's right.
I forgot.
You were never very good
at those, were you?
[PISTOLERA'S "NUEVOS OJOS"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Can I help you?
Yes, sir.
We wondered if
we could take a look around.
Why?
Sorry, what's your name?
Dennis.
Dennis. Hey.
I'm Steve Gomez.
I'm with the DEA.
Drug Enforcement.
Is there a problem?
For you? No. No problem.
We were just wondering
if we could take a look around.
Can I tell you a story?
Yeah.
I bust this chef.
Well, he says he's a chef.
Because you work at a restaurant
that charges $14 for a burger
that don't make you a chef.
Makes you a burger-flipper.
Least in my book.
Yeah.
Anyway, so we bust this chef,
heroin possession.
He says, "Just because you found
heroin in my chef whites
"doesn't make it mine.
Maybe it came from the place
that launders my chef whites."
This place.
We don't do that stuff
over here.
I know, I know.
I'll say it for you.
His story is a big load
of steaming horse shit.
We're gonna find heroin here
like we're gonna find
Jimmy Hoffa. Right?
The thing is that this
chef's daddy
is a United States
senator.
I'm not gonna tell which one,
but you know who he is.
So now I gotta waste my time
checking out this
burger-flipper's story.
If I don't,
his old man's gonna jam me up.
my ASAC,
my whole entire office.
Politics, huh?
So, what do you think?
Listen, I have to check with
my boss. He's out of town.
I can't promise
I'll reach him anytime soon.
Well, yeah.
That's probably the way to go.
I'll have to go get a warrant
and we'll do it official.
You have to close down
for the day.
What--? Why?
Twenty agents poking around?
It'd be less trouble
if it was just us.
But your call.
Just the two of you?
You make it quick, right?
Dennis,
we'll be like the wind.
Okay.
Could you tell him?
Can you clear out
some of your people for us?
Confuses the dog's nose.
[WHISTLES
THEN SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
[MACHINE POWERS DOWN]
So
how long we gotta be quiet
down here?
And what happens after this?
Provided they don't find their
way in here and bust our asses?
I gotta be, like, snuck down
here in a laundry hamper
for the rest of eternity?
Now, I'm going on record.
This blows.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
For you.
[SCOFFS]
Yeah?
GUS:
Do you know
what's happening upstairs?
I have a pretty good idea.
This is all the result
of your former partner.
Do you understand now?
Do you see why this can't
continue?
I get it. The guy
is a complete and total dick.
But I can't.
I'm not signing off.
Okay?
Like I said,
if something final happens
to Mr. White,
we're going to have a problem.
So, what are you gonna do?
There will be
an appropriate response.
Appropriate?
What does that mean?
Hello?
They're gone.
We're good.
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
[PHONE KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGING]
WALT [ON RECORDING]:
You have reached Walter White.
Please state your name, number
and the reason for your call.
Thank you.
[LINE BEEPS]
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
FEMALE VOICE:
You have six new messages.
SAUL:
Hey, kid. It's me, Goodman.
Give me a call, would you?
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
SAUL:
Hey, need to hear from you.
Hope I made myself clear
about that.
Call me as soon as you can.
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
SAUL:
Pinkman, get over here.
Stat, pronto.
Don't call, just get over here.
Would you just, please?
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
SAUL:
I don't know
if I'm speaking English here--
What's up?
He's waiting for me.
Hold up. Hold up.
What the hell, man?
Get off of me. Hey, Goodman.
Get out here.
Hey. Yo,
get your goon off me.
Not him, moron. Drop.
Leave it. Go lie down.
Sorry. You can't be
too careful these days.
Come on, come on.
Lock the door, Frisky. Jesus.
Take a break, H.T. Let's go.
Stop calling me that
or I'll hang you by your tie.
Yeah, yeah.
Stop showing off for the client.
Honey Tits.
I say it's endearing.
So, what's so important?
Well, they're here.
The end times, kid.
End times.
JESSE:
What does that mean?
Why'd you drag me here for?
You want your money, don't you?
I assume that you do.
JESSE:
That couldn't wait?
Ever hear of the expression,
"A fart in the wind"?
Inside of an hour,
that will be me,
I'm hitting the road.
I'm out of here.
What, for, like, good?
For as long as it takes.
I don't like my heat so hot
if you catch my drift.
I'm not catching anything
you're saying.
What is your problem?
You haven't talked to your
partner?
Not since last night.
Today,
he didn't show up to work
and the DEA just happened
to raid us.
Yeah,
some coincidence, huh?
I don't know about that.
All I know is when he tells me
that your employer took him out
threatening to murder
his family, I take notice.
Because after all,
what am I, if not family?
What are you talking about?
When did that happen?
I don't know. Forget it.
I mean, he exaggerates, right?
He does that.
Hey, listen. Do me a favor.
Put in a good word for me
with Fring.
I mean,
just for old time's sake.
I can't afford to butter
the wrong bread here.
Yeah?
[SIGHS]
Hey.
Nothing, huh?
HANK:
Clean as a whistle,
so he says.
[KEYPAD BEEPS]
[LINE RINGING]
WALT [ON RECORDING]:
You've reached Walter White.
State your name, number
and the reason for your call.
Thank you.
[LINE BEEPS]
It's me again.
I really wish you'd pick up.
God, I just...
Call me back, okay?
Just, um...
Just call me back, please.
[HOLLY BABBLING]
[♪♪♪]
Hi. I'm sorry.
Is it okay if I come out here
for a few minutes?
Sure. Just stay up here,
if you would.
Okay.
Excuse me.
I wonder if you have a--
An extra cigarette.
I sure could use a smoke
right about now.
Sure.
Thank you.
Thanks.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATING]
Hey, what's up?
What?
Hey. Hey.
What's wrong with him?
What hospital?
Andrea.
Jesse.
Where's Brock?
Inside.
Grandma's with him.
They got me filling
all this paperwork.
How is he doing? Tell me.
The doctors, they don't know
what it is exactly.
It's like he's got the flu.
But he just keeps
getting worse.
Jesse, I don't understand.
He was fine this morning.
He was fine.
Andrea Cantillo?
ANDREA:
Right here.
NURSE:
Miss Cantillo,
we're gonna go admit your son
to the Pediatric ICU.
You can bring that
with you.
Okay.
Sir,
you're the boy's father?
No.
Okay. Sorry. It's just we try to
keep it to two visitors maximum.
Go, go, go. I'll be out here
if you need me. Go. Go ahead.
[♪♪♪]
No.
No, no.
No. No. No.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
No. No!
[GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
Andrea!
Andrea.
Hey. No yelling.
I need to--
We can't have you here.
I need to talk to her.
I need to tell her--
Take this outside.
My son is sick in here.
No, just-- Come here.
ANDREA:
Jesse...
What is it?
Jesse, I can't go out.
My son's in here.
Okay. I'm thinking Brock
may have been poisoned, okay?
What?
There's this stuff,
this stuff called ricin.
Sounds like rice. You need
to tell the doctors about it.
What? How do you know?
Doesn't matter. Just tell them
it's a guess. Okay?
Ricin. They'll know
what you're talking about.
Jesse, if there's something
you're not saying,
you have to tell me.
I gotta go.
I gotta go see someone.
ANDREA: Jesse.
I'm sorry, I gotta go.
Just tell them, okay?
Now. Just do it.
Hello.
Could you buzz me in, please?
Buzz me in!
[DOOR BUZZES]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
What do you want?
JESSE:
We need to talk.
Who's with you?
JESSE:
No one. Just me.
Let me in.
I don't know what
you're thinking coming here.
Oh, Christ.
What does it matter?
Everything, it's all
coming to an end.
Do you even know
what's happening?
The full scope
of what's happening?
They took me
out into the desert.
They put a hood over my head
and drove me out into the desert
on my knees.
They threatened my family
and not just Hank.
My wife, my children.
It's just a matter of time now.
I was able to protect them
for now, but...
Gus is gonna make his move.
[TIRES SCREECH IN DISTANCE]
And I don't--
I don't know when.
I don't know where or how.
All I know is
it's gonna happen.
And I'm powerless
to stop him.
What are you doing?
Why did you do it?
Why?
Jesse.
Gus gave me no choice.
I had to call the DEA
to protect my family.
What else could I do--?
No. No, you son of a bitch.
You know what you did.
Okay, look, just--
Just put the gun down,
okay?
Just put it down and we'll talk,
all right?
You tell me
what it is you think I did.
Brock.
Why did you poison him?
Who's Brock?
You saw him in my
living room.
You came and you
looked right at him,
so don't tell me
you don't know him.
The boy?
Jesse, I have no idea
who these people are.
Now, please.
Okay, that's Brock
and he was poisoned?
The ricin.
He's dying because
someone gave it to him.
And only you and I were
the only two people on earth
who knew about it.
No, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Maybe he went
into your pockets--
No! I had it.
I had the cigarette with the
ricin in my pack this morning.
The last time I saw Brock
was last night.
And this morning, I switched
the cigarette into a new pack.
There's no way
Brock took it himself.
Jesse,
you're not thinking clearly.
You said it yourself
that you had it this morning.
When could I have possibly
gotten it?
You had Saul do it.
What?
Yeah.
Yeah. I went to his office.
He called me in,
had to see me today.
His big bodyguard
patted me down.
That's when he must have
stole it off me. Right?
That's the plan?
Was that the plan?
Jesse.
Why?
Why in God's name
would I poison a child?
To get back at me.
Because I'm helping Gus,
and this is your way
of ripping my heart out
before you're dead and gone.
Just admit it.
Admit what you did.
Admit it.
I did not do this!
Shut up!
Stop lying!
Look, I'm not lying.
I'm not lying.
Just listen to me.
What would I have to gain?
What possible--?
Possible could I--?
Who--? Who would--?
Oh, my God.
Hey.
[LAUGHING]
Stop laughing.
Stop laughing!
I have been waiting--
I've been waiting all day,
waiting for Gus to send
one of his men to kill me.
And it's you.
Who do you know
who's okay with using children?
Jesse, who do you know who's
allowed children to be murdered?
Gus.
He has been 10 steps ahead of me
at every turn.
And now, the one thing that he
needed to finally get rid of me
is your consent. And, boy,
he's got that now. He's got it.
And not only does
he have that
he manipulated you into
pulling the trigger for him.
No, only you and I
knew about the ricin.
No, you don't even
believe that.
Gus has cameras everywhere.
Please.
Listen to yourself.
No, he has known everything
all along.
Where were you today?
In the lab?
You don't think it's possible
that Tyrus
lifted the cigarette
out of your locker?
Come on.
Don't you see?
You are the last piece
of the puzzle.
You are everything
that he's wanted.
You're his cook now.
You're the cook
and you have proven that
you can run a lab without me.
And now that cook
has a reason to kill me.
Think about it.
It's brilliant.
So go ahead.
Go on.
If you think that I am capable
of doing this,
then go put a bullet in my head
and kill me right now.
I'll do it.
Do it!
Do it.
I'll do it.
[CRYING]
Where are you going?
Find the son of a bitch,
and I'm gonna kill him.
No.
Don't.
He'll see you coming.
You'll die before
you get anywhere near him.
I don't care.
Jesse.
Jesse,
just get in your car.
Just go.
Just drive.
No.
I'm going to do this
one way or another, Mr. White.
Then let me help.
NURSE:
Ah, Jesus. Mr. Pinkman,
I'm not gonna keep telling you.
Unless the family wants you
in there, you're not allowed.
You can't keep coming in here
like this.
You hear me?
You understand?
Mr. Pinkman,
I'm gonna call security.
All right, here I go.
Come on now.
Mr. Pinkman,
final warning.
Hey.
[SIGHS]
You need to be at work,
now.
I already told you.
I'm not going.
Got a batch
that'll be ruined,
and an employer who will be
very upset if that happens.
And I could give a shit.
I'm not leaving here.
If my employer
has a problem with that,
he can tell me
himself.
Not his errand boy.
Idiot.
Unh! Hey,
I don't know this guy!
Call security!
I'm being attacked!
Yeah. That's right.
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
We've got a situation.
[♪♪♪]
[DRILL WHIRRING]
[PHONE BEEPS]
[WALKIE-TALKIE CLICKS ON]
[WALKIE-TALKIE CHIRPING]
[♪♪♪]
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
He'd like to speak with you.
I told you, I'm not leaving.
He's downstairs.
[DOOR OPENS]
Tyrus told me
what's happening.
The sick child.
I understand
your preoccupation,
but, Jesse,
I am running a business.
I need you back at the lab
to complete the cook.
You can return
when you're done.
I can't.
It is, as you must know,
in both of our best interests.
That little boy upstairs
is dying.
I can't be away.
I don't even wanna be here now.
I can't be away,
if something happens, if he--
I am very sorry.
Is there anything
I can do?
I am on the board
of this hospital.
I can recommend doctors,
make sure he gets
whatever he needs.
The best treatment.
He's not sick.
He was poisoned.
How did that happen?
The doctors,
they don't know.
This current batch
is surely ruined now, correct?
Stay with the boy.
Tyrus will dump what's there
and clean the tanks.
You will start a new batch
when you are ready to return.
Next week.
[♪♪♪]
There you are.
[CLICKS ON]
Keep going.
[CHUCKLES]
Why did you stop?
Come on. Come on.
[♪♪♪]
No, no, no.
Don't go, don't go, don't go.
No. No.
Oh, shit.
No.
[♪♪♪]