MAN: Honey mustard.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
As per the Research Department
this is our sweeter formulation
for the American Midwest.
While we've upped its Brix
number by 14 percent,
we in fact use 2.2 percent
less honey
and make up the balance
with high-fructose corn syrup.
We're quite pleased
with the result.
This one is a new concept
and it intrigues us--
Half French dressing,
half ranch.
We refer to it simply as
"Franch."
Though perhaps our friends
in the Marketing Department
will see fit to come up
with a more catchy.
Any thoughts on the Franch?
Is it perhaps too...?
Cajun Kick-Ass.
This again is a reformulation
designed to alleviate
the potential
for gastric distress brought on.
Brought on by the original.
Smoky Mesquite B-B-Q...
containing 3 percent more
smoke flavor.
And
ketchup.
That last one is essentially
just ketchup.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Mr. Schuler, they're back.
Three this time.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Tell them I'll be with them
shortly.
Thank you, Ms. Tromel.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(BEEPING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(MS. TROMEL SPEAKING)
Mr. Schuler? Are you in there?
Yes, Ms. Tromel.
I'm sorry, sir--
These men
they're really rather insistent.
Mr. Schuler?
(KNOCKING LOUDLY)
(MAN SPEAKING GERMAN)
Mr. Schuler,
this is Chief Inspector Kunst.
I'd like a word, please.
Would you step out
of the washroom?
(KNOCKING LOUDLY)
Mr. Schuler, open this door.
Now, Mr. Schuler.
(KNOCKING LOUDLY)
Open up.
(DOOR THUDDING)
Mr. Schuler!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(WHIRRING)
(ELECTRICAL ARC)
(FLUSHING)
(BANGING ON DOOR CONTINUES)
JESSE: (ON PHONE)
Honest to God, it's starting
to drive me crazy.
WALTER: Well, don't.
It keeps me awake at night.
I lay there thinking, "Where is
it? Where did it go?"
And I just...
You know, I can't even...
I have no idea.
Jesse... Jesse, look.
Doesn't it make sense
that it wound up in the lab?
I thought about that a lot.
But I just don't see how.
Well, look.
You had the pack
in your pocket
of your jacket, right?
Yeah.
Your jacket was in your locker.
So maybe the cigarette
just fell out of the pocket
and wound up in the locker,
and now it's all burned up.
It's gone.
Yeah.
But I don't know that,
you know?
I can't ever know
for sure.
(SIGHS)
Well, look, did you
check your house?
Did you... Maybe it's
somewhere in your house.
No, man. I've looked
everywhere, okay?
Did you check your car?
No, no...
Thoroughly?
Yes, of course.
Look, it's not in my house.
It's not in my car.
And the more I think about it,
there's no way
it fell out in my locker.
And I keep thinking somebody's
gonna find this thing
on the street or something.
You don't know that.
Somewhere where I dropped it.
No.
Some innocent person,
some kid maybe, even.
No. No. come on.
And they're gonna
pick it up, and it's gonna...
You're working
yourself all up.
Oh, my God!
Jesse, listen.
You've gotta get
ahold of yourself here.
All right? I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna
come over there.
And together, we're gonna
look for this thing.
All right?
Yeah.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
Ohh.
(WHIRRING)
What the hell is that?
My Roomba.
I already checked it.
When?
Like, a week ago.
Oh, God.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay. Easy, easy.
Take it...
Careful. Let me see.
Is it still intact?
Yeah. Good.
Good. No worries.
Let me get rid of this.
What luck.
Whoo.
(TOILET FLUSHES)
Well, I don't know
about you,
but I, for one,
could use a beer.
You have any?
Jesse?
(SOBBING)
I almost shot you.
Hey, hey, now...
I almost killed you
all because...
Listen.
It was just a...
A misunderstanding, that's all.
No. No, no, no, no.
I don't know what's wrong
with me, Mr. White.
I...
Hey.
(CRYING)
I don't know how
I could be so stupid.
Stop that now. Come on.
Come on. Come on.
I'm so sorry.
Shh. Shh.
It's okay.
(CONTINUES CRYING)
Listen to me.
What happened, happened for
the best, you hear me?
And I wouldn't
change a thing.
You and I
working together,
having each other's back.
It's what saved our lives.
I...
I want you to think about that
as we go forward.
Go forward where?
(CHATTER ON TV)
MAN: (ON TV) Stillwell,
steady as she goes.
Ohh.
Willie, note the time.
Whoo.
Ohh.
Captain, I'm sorry,
but you're a sick man.
Mmm.
I'm relieving you
as captain of the ship
under article 184.
Oh, God.
CAPTAIN: I don't
know what you're talking about.
Helmsman, left 180.
Ohh.
Mr. Keith,
what do I do?
You're the officer on the deck.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I told you to come left.
Now come left, and fast.
MAN 1:
I'm sorry, sir,
but you're not issuing orders
on this bridge anymore.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
I've relieved you.
I take full responsibil...
(TURNS OFF TV)
WALTER:
Thanks for seeing us.
WALTER: We're here
to talk partnership.
Partnership.
Yes. Equal.
Three ways.
You, Jesse and me.
Partnership in what?
Well, we figure we're gonna
start cooking again.
You know,
we figure, why not?
There's no denying
the popularity of our product.
There's a market
to be filled,
and currently
no one to fill it.
JESSE: A lot of
money to be made.
And obviously, Jesse and I
have manufacture covered.
But there's
still distribution,
support, logistics,
that sort of thing.
For instance, we'll need
a steady supply of precursor.
With your experience
and connections,
you would be
a great help.
Mmm.
Granted, there's
a lot of work ahead.
There's a lot
of rebuilding.
And, no doubt,
our profits will be smaller.
At least at first.
But each of us
will receive a larger cut.
Owners, not employees.
Thanks, but no, thanks.
Mike,
I know you don't
care for me.
We've had our issues,
you and I.
But I would suggest
that you leave emotion
out of this decision.
I am.
You
are trouble.
I'm sorry the kid here
doesn't see it,
but I sure as hell do.
You are a time bomb
tick, tick, ticking,
and I have no intention
of being around for the boom.
Well, sleep on it.
Maybe you'll reconsider.
In the meantime,
we're pressing on.
Morning.
Hey, why aren't
you upstairs?
I came to see if
you needed any help.
Yeah, well, I don't.
Well, I can see that, man.
It's outstanding.
Yeah.
I'm working on it here.
Not exactly running marathons
here, you know.
Yeah, well, when did
your couch-shaped ass
ever run
any marathons?
I'm proud of you, brother.
Yeah, yeah.
So how many Krauts we got?
Enough to invade Poland.
Came in their own G5,
just like Oprah has.
G5, yeah?
Mmm-hmm.
Is that one where the...
Where the wings go up like that?
I think they all do that.
They all have that?
Anyway, we got two
U.S. Attorneys in the house.
Big doings.
Your name keeps coming up.
Yeah? Hey, give me
a hand here, would you?
Just... Just a little bit
there. Thanks.
HERZOG: I hired
Peter Schuler in 1992.
Almost single-handedly,
he grew our
little restaurant division
into an industry leader
and a source
of great personal pride.
I am shocked and saddened
by his death
and outraged
by the damage
his actions have wrought
upon my grandfather's company.
(SPEAKS GERMAN)
Alleged actions.
An innocent man
does not kill himself.
My people and I
are here to help.
To your investigation,
I pledge Madrigal's
full cooperation
and transparency.
I confess I have
my selfish reasons.
I believe Peter Schuler
was a lone anomaly.
But if that
is not the case,
I want to know it,
just as you do.
So when you gonna
announce it?
I don't know.
As I'm walking out the door
with my big cardboard box.
Can't do that.
You know damn well we're gonna
throw you a big party.
Damn straight.
We're talking a blowout.
Outstanding
police work, Hank.
If only I'd listened.
But I guess
the damage was done.
It's not right,
them putting this on you.
Somebody's gotta
go under the bus.
Ramey's a good man.
He'll do right by you.
Besides, this office
practically runs itself.
Bullshit it does.
Sir.
What's with that APD thing?
The electromagnets?
They're thinking
it's about Fring's laptop.
Turns out a couple of days
before it happened,
desk sergeant gets this phone
call from a "postal inspector,"
quote, unquote,
wanting to know
where they keep the thing.
And he told them?
Jesus.
Anything left
of the laptop?
(SCOFFS)
Do we look that lucky?
You know, I sneaked a peek
before APD took it out of
Fring's office.
The whole thing
was encrypted.
They wouldn't have got
anything anyway, but...
So Hector Salamanca
killed Fring.
But who gave Salamanca
the bomb?
(SIGHS) Whole lot
of questions
and not much
in the way of answers.
Yet.
The APD did find
some of Fring's financials.
That just might
lead to something.
I had him out
to my house.
4th of July.
We cooked
out in the backyard.
My son shucked the corn.
My daughter cut up potatoes.
Fring brought sea bass.
Every time
I grill it now,
I make a little foil pouch,
just like he showed me.
That whole night,
we were laughing,
telling stories,
drinking wine.
And he's somebody else
completely.
Right in front of me.
Right under my nose.
Hi.
What can I get you?
Just tea, please.
Chamomile.
Oh, sorry.
We don't have chamomile tea.
Then some sort of bergamot,
provided it's not Earl Grey.
I like soy milk
instead of dairy.
We don't have soy milk
or any sort of bergamot.
Wow. You're really running me
through my paces here.
Uh-huh.
Well, English Breakfast,
I guess.
We have Lipton's.
That's pretty much
all we have.
I would like a cup of
hot water, filtered,
if possible,
and a single slice of lemon.
And I'm assuming
you don't have Stevia?
Never mind.
I brought my own.
You coming to me,
or am I coming to you?
Face forward.
We'll talk like this.
I guess
I'm coming to you.
Ohh.
Mmm.
Take a breath,
will you?
This place is safe.
No one's gonna see you here.
My God!
Duane, this is so...
Thank you.
How did I not see you
sitting back there?
So weird.
(CHUCKLES)
You want anything else,
Mike?
No.
I'm good, Fran.
Thanks.
Now,
how about
we lose the sunglasses?
I feel like I'm talking
to Jackie Onassis here.
There you go.
Breathe in,
breathe out.
Drink your whatever.
Who killed Gus?
Haven't I told you
not to worry about that?
Now, what do you want from me,
and why is it so important?
What's this?
A list of 11 names.
Okay.
You know them all.
I do.
Those 11 men... And I
think you know this, Mike.
Those 11 could sink us,
you and me both.
Where are we going
with this, Lydia?
No specific.
I'm just pointing out facts.
These men... Your men...
Yours and Gus's...
These men were on
the payroll, very publicly.
They trace back to Pollos
and the laundry.
They trace back to Madrigal,
and they're gonna get
picked up by the police.
And when they do,
when they get picked up
and threatened
with prosecution,
and there's only one way out
for them, they're gonna...
And I'm not saying
all of them, okay?
All it's gonna take is
two or three, or even one.
But there's always
a weak link somewhere.
But they're gonna talk.
At least one of them's
gonna talk about you,
about me, and that's all
it's gonna take.
These are the 11 I know of,
but I'd love your input.
I never met your chemist,
for instance.
I'd love your input.
You want me to kill
every man on that list?
Wow. That's a leap,
what you just, uh...
No, I didn't say that.
But if you think
that'd be wise...
(SIGHS)
You're scared,
aren't you?
Yeah.
You're very upset,
which I'm gonna factor
into my response here.
These are my guys,
and they are solid.
Understand?
What about Chow
at the warehouse?
Didn't one time you have
to shoot him through the hand?
You think that didn't
stick in his memory?
What about Dennis
at the laundry?
They're sure
to pick him up.
They already have.
They picked him up last night.
My guys are solid.
I vetted them
with great care,
and Fring made sure
they were well compensated
in the event
of a situation such as this.
They're paid
to stand up to the heat,
keep their mouths shut,
no matter what.
And they will.
Now, I don't know
what kind of movies
you've been watching,
but here in the real world,
we don't kill 11 people
as some kind of
prophylactic measure.
Look at me
and say you understand.
I understand.
I get it.
So we're off
that very silly idea?
Good.
Drink your hot water.
I gotta go.
Did you have enough?
Yeah. I'm good.
Okay.
(QUIETLY)
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Bye, big brother.
(CHUCKLES)
Say bye to Mom for me.
I will.
Have a good day.
You, too.
(DOOR OPENS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(QUIETLY) Skyler.
Mmm...
Hey.
The car wash opens
in 15 minutes.
Mariano can open
for me today.
Hey, how about
you get up, huh?
Come on.
A shower
will feel good.
Hey, Chow.
How you holding up?
Okay.
You know, they...
They...
They talked to me.
You can't smoke
in here, Chow.
HANK:
Thanks for coming down.
Have a seat, Mr., uh,
Ehrmantraut.
Am I, uh,
saying that right?
Close enough.
So, once more,
you're waiving your right
to have an attorney present?
Correct.
Could you state that
to the camera, please?
I'm waiving my right
to have an attorney present.
Uh, okay, then.
We just have a few questions.
You're currently employed
by the Pollos Hermanos chain.
Is that correct?
Yes, I am.
And what do
you do there?
Corporate security.
Yeah.
What's that? Like, uh,
guarding the special sauce?
I conduct employee
background checks.
I oversee
loss prevention.
At a fast-food restaurant,
that's a full-time job?
We have 14 locations.
So, yes, it's a full-time job.
Yeah, well,
(CHUCKLES)
If I were you, I'd start
sending out those resumes.
It says here you're
a private investigator?
Where you licensed?
New Mexico,
Arizona, Utah.
Every state
where we operate.
Colorado? You have some
restaurants there, right?
Colorado doesn't
require licensure.
You licensed
to carry a firearm?
Concealed carry?
Yes, I am.
Which states?
It'd be quicker to mention
the states in which I'm not.
And if we pulled
your C.C.P.'s,
everything would be
in order?
I'm guessing
you've already done that,
so you tell me.
You strike me
as a former cop.
Am I right?
Where at?
Philadelphia.
Philly.
(CHUCKLES)
The city of brotherly love.
Turns out we, uh,
we know some folks there,
and they told us
that your tenure
as a police officer
ended somewhat,
uh, dramatically?
You wanna talk
about that?
Not particularly.
Yeah, me neither.
See, I'm more interested
in why Gus Fring
decided to put
a guy like you
in charge of
his corporate security.
I mean,
given your history
doing background checks
on pimple-faced fry cooks.
Seems like overkill.
What else you do
for Fring?
He must've needed help running
that drug empire of his, no?
Drug empire?
First I'm hearing
about that.
I don't know anything
Hey, man, we have a guy that
could put you in that
underground lab,
and he'll testify to it.
So from here on out,
this can go hard or easy.
So what's it gonna be?
Forget your handcuffs?
I'm confused.
Am I under arrest here,
or am I not?
You wanna state that
for the camera?
You are not under arrest,
currently.
Agents, do you have
any more questions for me?
Because you've got me
very stirred up
with all these
false accusations.
If I'm not under arrest,
I'd prefer to leave.
Oh, well...
Uh-huh.
And I suppose
we could talk about
the two million dollars
in your
granddaughter's name.
Yeah. It seems, uh,
Fring had all these
secret offshore accounts
that he would
deposit money into.
Like, uh, well,
an even dozen of them.
And they're all
in the names
of certain people
on his payroll.
There was the, uh,
the manager of the laundry,
um, a couple guys from the
Pollos distribution center.
There was the owner
of a chemical warehouse,
a bunch of others.
You know, guys that must've been
getting paid off the books.
Anyway, one of the names
was Kaylee Ehrmantraut.
Ten years old
and just cute as a button.
Yeah. Two million and change
we found on deposit for her.
Way more
than anybody else.
Now, my partner here,
he took one look at that
and said, "Shit, man.
"This fifth-grade girl
is the muscle behind
Fring's entire operation."
I said, "Whoa, whoa.
Hey, partner, slow down there.
"Maybe it was actually
"her dear old granddaddy."
Impressive, no?
That... (CLICKS TONGUE)
level of insight?
He's not impressed,
Gomie.
Perhaps he's picturing
all that money going bye-bye.
Yeah, well, I mean,
the government's gonna take
every last dollar, unless...
Well, here's the thing,
Mike... Or Michael?
Mr. Ehrmantraut.
Here's the thing, Mike.
Lucky for you,
you didn't touch that money.
I cannot say the same
for the other 11 on the list.
One of your guys
is gonna roll on you,
and then we'll definitely
remember the handcuffs.
Now, before that day comes,
you can do yourself a solid.
You can tell us
what you know,
you can tell us
who's still out there,
and if we like your story,
good things can happen.
Kaylee might be able
to keep some of that money.
Maybe.
HANK: So what do you say?
I don't know anything
about any money.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
WALTER:
First order of business
is to find
a new place to cook.
Before anyone says it,
no more RV's.
I don't know. The crystal ship
did pretty good for us.
The "crystal ship"?
Yeah.
That's what I called it.
Well, I'll admit, it held
its own as a starter lab,
but it was too dark,
too small,
not to mention it could've
broken down at any moment.
Saul, find us someplace
safe from prying eyes.
Security against detection
is paramount.
But I don't wanna
drive too far.
No more 50-mile treks
to some Indian reservation.
In town is trickier.
I mean, you got a lot more
of your prying eyes.
If Gus can manage it,
then so can we.
Precursor.
Where are we with that?
Uh, we're good
on everything
except, uh,
methylamine.
No surprise.
It's dry as hell
out there.
What if we switched back
to a pseudo cook?
Absolutely
out of the question.
Jesse, there is methylamine
out there. I know it.
Yeah, but what if
there's not?
Because there isn't.
I mean, really.
There is.
Have faith.
Can I...
Can I offer a thought?
Uh...
Say a guy
wins the lottery.
Ten million bucks.
The very next day, what's
the one thing he does not do?
He does not go buy another
lottery ticket, right?
He counts his lucky stars, and
he sails off into the sunset,
which, seems to me,
and all due respect,
some advice you two
might take.
What lottery
did I win exactly?
Hey, you're alive.
I mean, as far as I'm concerned,
that's the Irish sweepstakes.
I'm alive, and I'm broke.
Counting the money
that I owe Jesse,
I'm about 40 grand
in the hole.
Does that seem like
an acceptable
stopping point to you?
(SIGHS)
There is gold
in the streets,
just waiting for someone
to come and scoop it up.
But me,
I should quit now.
Jesse, too,
I suppose, huh?
Wow.
I got you
this time, kid.
And how come you get two,
and I only get one?
Hmm?
Oh, no, you don't.
That one's mine!
(MUTTERS)
No. (GROANS)
(PHONE BUZZING)
Oh!
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
I give up, baby.
You're too good.
Yeah?
CHOW: It's me.
You got a minute?
Yeah. A minute.
What's up, Chow?
The DEA,
they call me to come back.
Say they want to talk more.
I'm sure they do.
Did you call your lawyer?
Yeah, but, Mike,
the DEA take all my money.
I need it.
I need my money.
You understand.
What do you want me
to do about it?
I don't know.
We gotta talk.
Not on the phone.
Can you come
to my house?
All right.
Give me two hours.
(BEEPS)
(WHIRRING)
(SOFT THUDDING)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
MIKE: Chris.
I'd like you
to drop your gun
where you stand,
and then turn around
very slowly.
(GUN CLATTERS)
(SIGHS)
Come on over
and sit next to Chow.
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES FORCEFULLY)
How much
was she gonna pay you?
Ten thousand a name.
How far did you get
down the list?
Just Chow.
I figured
I'd start with you.
For you,
she was gonna pay 30,000.
I'm really sorry
about this, Mike,
but I needed the money.
Those feds,
they took it all, man.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I know.
Are you ready?
Listen, Mike...
(GUN FIRING)
(SHELLS CLATTER)
(EXHALES)
DELORES:
Kiira, come and have
some cookies.
KIIRA: It's a cookie!
It's a cookie, yes!
Let's go. Uh-huh.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Let's count.
BOTH:
Uno. Dos. Tres.
Cuatro.
Mmm-hmm.
Cinco.
Seis.
Seis. Muy bien.
Siete.
BOTH: Ocho.
Nueve. Diez.
(NANNY SPEAKING SPANISH)
Amarillo.
Rosado.
Azul.
Verde.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Well, look at this.
What are you doing?
Hey, Mommy!
What are you doing still up?
Hey, yourself.
Give me a kiss.
She said she wanted
to wait for you.
She does, huh?
Well, who's the adult
here, Delores?
Tell me she ate
her dinner, at least.
DELORES: Oh, yes,
she ate everything.
She ate her peas,
she ate her carrots.
(WHISPERING)
Do whatever it takes
to keep them out of here,
or they die.
She ate a whole lot of carrots.
Understand?
KIIRA: Yep.
DELORES:
That's right, my girl.
Delores,
I'm gonna take a bath.
Put Kiira to bed and then go on
home. I'll see you tomorrow.
Really? You don't want me
to wait for you?
No, you go home.
Thank you.
Si, Miss Lydia.
Buenas noches.
Mommy, you gonna come
say good night to me?
Yeah, honey.
After Mommy takes a bath.
Okay.
Love you.
DELORES:
Mommy's very tired,
so let's go to bed.
(GASPS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Don't hurt my daughter.
I won't have to
unless you scream.
You know why I'm here?
What are you
waiting for?
The nanny to leave.
If you have anything
to say to me,
now's the time.
(SCOFFS)
Two good men died
because of you.
Don't shoot me
in the face.
Please.
I don't want my daughter
seeing me like that.
Your daughter won't see you.
Yes, she will.
She'll find me.
She never once
sleeps through the night.
Nobody's gonna
find you, Lydia.
Wait. What?
No.
No. No.
No! She has to find me.
Lower your voice.
(WHISPERING)
She has to find me.
I... I...
You want your
five-year-old daughter
stumbling across
your dead body?
I can't just disappear. She has
to know I didn't leave her.
She has to know that!
Keep your voice down.
I don't care
what you do.
I'll scream,
and I'll keep screaming.
My daughter's not thinking
I abandoned her!
Shut up and calm down.
I don't care.
You have to promise.
You have to promise me...
(BEEPS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Promise I don't disappear.
(SIGHS)
Can you still get
your hands on methylamine?
Methylamine, Lydia.
Can you still get it?
Maybe.
Why?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BEEPS)
(PHONE BUZZING)
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
Yes?
MIKE:
You still plan
to move forward?
Yes, we do.
I've reconsidered.
I'm in.
Good.
(GRUNTING)
Well, you missed
a good meal.
The lasagna
came out very well,
if I do say so myself.
I wrapped some up for you
if you'd like some later.
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES FORCEFULLY)
You know,
it gets easier.
I promise you
that it does.
What you're feeling
right now,
about, uh, Ted...
Everything.
It'll pass.
(SIGHS)
When we do
what we do
for good reasons,
then we've got
nothing to worry about.
And there's
no better reason
than family.