[BEEPING]
Hey, Darla.
How you doing today?
Hey, Dan.
I'm looking for
something in a Markowski.
That'd be, uh,
Dennis Markowski?
That's the one.
[BEEPING]
Oh, and I've got my, uh,
paralegal with me today.
Paralegal?
Coming up in the world.
You know it.
[INAUDIBLE]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Dennis.
Have a seat.
[ROCK MUSIC ON EARPHONES]
You hear about Chow?
Yeah, people say
he skipped town.
He's dead.
It wasn't me.
It wasn't a message.
It wasn't payback.
It was a mistake
made by a third party
who has since
been dealt with.
You got it?
Yeah.
The second thing.
The deal
you had with Fring,
it's still in place.
Okay.
Don't "okay" me.
You got
something to say?
Mike, I'm keeping
my mouth shut.
The laundry
was right above the lab.
There's no way
I could say
I wasn't in on it.
I'm looking
at eight years minimum.
But I'm doing my time
like I'm supposed to.
I'm no rat,
and you know it.
What else
is there to say?
All due respect,
what are we
talking about here?
The deal is the deal.
How's the deal the deal?
The feds took away
my hazard pay.
My wife comes to me
and asks me where the
mortgage is coming from.
I got nothing
to tell her.
I knew the risks.
We all did.
But that
wasn't the deal.
And I know for a fact
they got Holt
and Perez yesterday.
Now, it's not gonna be me,
but absent the hazard pay,
sooner or later,
someone's gonna flip.
No one's flipping.
Everyone gets
their hazard pay,
including you.
I appreciate what
you're saying and all,
but the man is dead.
Okay? The lab's
a hole in the ground.
I just don't see it.
I've got something new.
It's just starting up.
It's gonna make you whole.
Something new?
With the feds looking at you?
How?
"How" is my business.
Hanging tight's
your business.
Your family's
gonna be fine.
You will be made whole.
Now, you got my word.
You need more?
No, Mike. I'm good.
MIKE: Who's next?
That's your choice.
APDs got Martinez
across town.
McGann's up in Sandoval.
The Sandia tribal cops are
holding him for the feds.
[ALARM BUZZES]
And Holt and Perez
are in lockup in Los Lunas.
You don't mean
to get to them all today?
Yeah, I do.
Hey, let's go!
Open up!
[ALARM BUZZES]
[♪♪♪]
[HUMMING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Back here!
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, hi.
How was your day?
Um, are... Are you
moving back in?
Yeah. I'll keep
the condo for now.
Selling it in this market,
I'd get killed.
But, yeah, I'm home.
It's time.
Do you, uh, really think
that's a good idea?
Yes.
[LABORED BREATHING]
[LABORED BREATHING CONTINUES]
SAUL:
So you bring him here? Come on.
The three of us,
we're the three amigos.
All for one,
one for all.
We don't need
a fourth amigo.
Saul,
Mike knows the business.
He knows distributors.
Mike's okay.
He's okay?
He said he was gonna
break my legs.
And don't tell me
he didn't mean it, okay?
'Cause he gave me
the dead mackerel eyes.
He meant it.
WALT:
Saul, Mike threatened me.
He threatened Jesse.
He probably threatened
someone before
breakfast this morning.
It's what he does.
Come on. Grow a pair.
Let it be noted
that I do this under duress.
Duly noted.
All right.
Let him in, Huell.
Mike,
I'm extending you the...
Uh-huh.
Now that we're all together,
here are the ground rules.
Division of labor.
I handle the business.
Making the stuff,
that's your end.
I don't tell you
how to mix your
chemicals and whatnot,
and you
do not tell me
how to take care
of business.
Is that
absolutely clear?
Sure.
All right.
Let's take the tour.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, you're okay
with that?
Yes.
He handles the business,
and I handle him.
SAUL:
Clearly, we're talking
about renting, not buying.
You need
an ongoing business,
someplace you can
slide in, do your thing,
and remain anonymous.
I'm not gonna
mince words.
This is your best bet.
Got machines running,
forklifts,
people coming and going.
You're gonna stay
way under the radar.
And the owner's solid.
He can't wait to
throw up a curtain wall,
stack some boxes
in front of it, give you
all the space you need.
After that,
he's got his business,
you've got yours,
and never the twain
shall meet.
It's outstanding.
Am I right?
Machines like this,
gotta be plenty of power.
What about the smell?
Ah. More good news.
I've been here
when it's up and running.
This place stinks already.
You'll blend right in.
How many employees?
Ha. I knew you'd ask.
Sixteen illegals,
all highly motivated
to stay deaf,
blind, and dumb.
You'll want to
vet them, I'm sure.
Yes, indeed.
So what do you say,
maestro?
Huh?
Is it unanimous?
You know,
I worked in a box factory
one summer in high school,
and I haven't seen
one of these in years.
Trip down memory lane.
That's perfect.
You know what this is?
It's a corrugator.
It uses steam and salt
to crimp kraft paper
for cardboard.
And it makes
a hell of a racket doing it,
which is great.
Right?
No.
Steam and salt.
When this thing is running,
it's like a jungle in here.
Shit.
It'll ruin the product.
You can't just
pop down to Costco
and get
a couple dehumidifiers?
What... Fine. Fine.
Moving on.
Spacious,
isolated location,
no humidity,
and you get all the
free tortillas you want.
That's the special feature
of this place.
I don't know.
It'll make the tortillas
smell like cat piss.
Somebody's bound
to notice that.
All right. Well,
there's gotta be some kind
of workaround, right?
It's a technical problem.
You guys are technical guys.
You know, be creative.
Put your heads together.
Anything food-related
is gonna have unannounced
government inspections.
All I'm asking is that
you keep an open mind.
Danny's already
set some space aside
behind the skee ball games.
[SCOFFS]
No.
Hell, no.
I know it's a long shot.
All I can say
to recommend this one
is we're talking about
an owner here who is,
how should I put it,
highly amenable.
Look, I get it.
Just say no,
and we'll go get dinner.
All right.
So I'll start.
No way we're
cooking in here.
No space,
nowhere for the smell to go.
Look at that door.
That thing rolls up,
and we're open to the world.
MIKE:
I don't know
if anybody noticed,
but there's a cop shop
a quarter of a mile away.
The hammer comes down,
it's gonna be
Custer's Last Stand.
It's perfect.
What?
How are we gonna
fit a lab in here?
Who said here?
WALT:
A house is infested.
Termites,
cockroaches, whatever.
Homeowners hire
a pest control company.
Truck rolls up,
homeowners leave.
The crew
tents the house.
They bomb the place
with poison.
The house stays
like that for days.
No one looks twice
at a tented house.
Now, maybe there's
a strange smell
coming out of it.
Does someone think
to investigate? No.
Does anyone go inside?
Hell, no.
And that's
where we'll cook.
They tent, what,
three, four houses a week?
So we pick the one
that's best for us.
Enough floor space,
easy access.
Once the tent is up,
we go in,
we cook a batch,
we bomb the place,
and leave.
So we gotta move
in and out for every cook?
Set up the lab, cook,
and then take everything down?
It's challenging
but doable.
Tell me
about these guys.
Uh, Mr. Ponytail
on the sidewalk, that's Ira.
He's the owner.
On the roof is Sandor.
The ladder's Fernando,
and down below, that's Todd.
The pest control operation
is legit.
I mean, they're licensed,
they're bonded,
they do as good a job
as anyone in town,
but they're also top-drawer
second-story men.
"Second-story"?
B&E artists.
They're burglars.
Yeah. I mean, hey,
they play it smart.
They don't boost anything
while they're on the job.
They copy the keys,
locate the valuables
and alarms,
and they sell
that information
to other crews.
Or, after a decent interval,
they'll come back and lift
the goods themselves.
And you know them how?
Oh, I've been pulling
their chestnuts
out of the fire,
legally speaking,
for five years.
Ira and his guys
are good.
I mean, they know how
to keep their mouths shut.
And if you buy them,
they're gonna stay bought.
You can check
into them yourself.
I will,
if it comes to that.
So, do we take a vote?
Why?
[HORN HONKS]
[PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC]
[DISCORDANT NOTES]
We sound great.
Rock on, man. Solid.
That Yamaha's got
a real nice touch.
You like the sound?
It's huge, huh?
Yeah, it's real nice,
but we're looking
for something else today.
You got
any roadie cases?
For sure. What size?
Biggest you got.
[PLAYS NOTE]
That'll fit through, like,
a regular-size doorway.
You got it.
Follow me.
Top of the line.
Recessed hardware,
foam lining,
quarter-inch
laminated walls,
three-inch casters.
Height is good,
width is good.
How much weight
will this hold?
It's rated for 900 pounds.
[FEEDBACK SOUNDING]
So unless your band
plays lead bricks,
you should be okay.
[PLAYING DRUMS]
We're gonna need, uh...
[PLAYING GUITAR]
Hey, man,
I'm trying to do business
over here, bitch.
Sorry. He's, like,
overly enthusiastic.
Anyway, um,
I'm gonna need four of them.
Four?
That gonna be layaway?
'Cause I need to see
a bunch of IDs for that.
No, man, cash.
Okay. Hey, uh,
you know what?
I'll throw in stenciling.
What's your band called?
SKINNY PETE:
Damn, brother!
Not asking no questions,
but it sure looks like
you're back in business.
No joke. You way back
in business, man.
Look at this.
Yeah.
Oh! You're stacking
the benjies
till the rubber band pops.
Yeah, yeah.
All's we're saying is,
we know you're
major league now.
But if there's
ever anything else
you need from us...
Any way we can
get in on this at all.
Little stuff, big stuff.
We would be
all over it.
You know, uh,
maybe someday.
That's cool.
I guess we better
hit it then.
Yeah. Keep on
keeping on, brother.
Later.
Yeah.
[DOOR CLOSING]
MIKE:
Okay, it is
the same job as always.
You go out, you inspect,
you deal with
the customers,
regular drill.
Everything's the same
except for one
important detail.
No stealing.
Not a toothpick,
not the spare change
between the couch cushions,
not the panties
out of the hamper.
Nothing.
And I mean nothing.
And if you're out
with your buddies
and they ask if you got
a hot tip on a B&E,
you tell them
you got nada.
You're out of the game.
The bottom line is
that these houses
are out of bounds
now and forever.
Got it?
All right.
From time to time,
you're gonna see these two.
Now, as far
as you're concerned,
they are ghosts.
You don't see them.
You don't hear them.
You don't
say "good morning."
You don't speak
unless you're spoken to.
On the other hand,
if they tell you to jump,
you don't ask what for,
you jump.
Now, you need
a name for them?
You call them "Yes, sir"
and "No, sir."
You got any problems,
you come to me.
JESSE:
Here's the deal.
The finishing tank's
a tight fit.
And with this motor
you've got on top...
WALT:
The agitation motor.
The agitation motor
here on top,
the tank's not gonna
fit in the box.
It's just, uh...
It's just too tall.
You know, I thought we'd
put a collar on the tank
and carry
the motor in separately,
alongside the condenser.
And on the day,
we just kind of
twist it into place,
you know,
while we're setting up.
Yeah.
That's good.
That will work.
And Joe and his guys
can build it, right?
Yeah.
You know, they're, uh...
They're up for it.
Joe already
bought a tig welder
for the aluminum work.
And, you know,
I figure if they
can pull off the magnet,
they can handle this.
Now, listen,
about the smell...
About keeping it
out of people's drapes
and furniture and whatnot...
When I was down
in Mexico, they, uh...
There was this big,
big plastic hospital tent
they set up inside of the...
[LOCK CLICKING]
Oh, shit. Sorry.
[DOOR OPENS]
Oh, hi. Sorry.
No, no, no.
We were just,
uh, wrapping up.
Um, this is my, uh...
Friend. Hi. Walt.
Nice to meet you.
You too.
JESSE:
This is, uh, Brock.
Hi, Brock. I'm Walt.
I've heard a lot
about you.
Hi.
I understand
you were in the hospital.
And Jesse told me
that you were very brave.
Yeah.
A man of few words.
I'm sorry.
He mostly just wants
to play his game.
Oh, I know that.
I have two of my own.
A boy and a girl.
[VIDEO GAME NOISES]
Well, I should, uh...
I should go.
I was thinking
I could make us
all some dinner.
Are you sure
you don't wanna...
Yeah. Won't you stay
for a beer at least?
Sure. Why not?
A beer sounds good.
Thank you.
[VIDEO GAME NOISES]
[SIGHS]
How are you today, sir?
Hello. We're good.
Good. How are you?
Family all packed up,
ready to go?
Okay,
here you're acknowledging
that you've removed all pets
and plants from the house
and that food has been removed
or double-sealed in the
bags we provided.
Uh-huh.
And this acknowledges
that you've removed or bagged
any medicines, tobacco,
and pet foods.
Better make sure
you got any medicine
you might need for
the next couple of days.
It's already in the car.
Okay.
Holy crap.
How much poison
are you using?
It's not how much,
it's getting it
to where it's needed.
Those are your foggers.
They disperse the fumigate
into the structure
where it'll eliminate
any nymphs or larvae
as well as
the full-grown blattodea.
So, uh, do we have
all your keys?
Any extras on here
you might wind up needing?
No. I'm good.
Okay.
This last one here
acknowledges that you
have been informed
that you may not
reenter the premises
until it has cleared the
post-fumigation inspection.
So you're gonna
get them all, right?
We'll kill 'em dead.
That's a guarantee.
Sir? Uh, sir?
Yes?
There's a nanny-cam
in the living room clock.
I disabled it.
I just thought
you should know.
What's your name?
Todd, sir.
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING]
[HISSING]
Hey, cheers.
Yeah.
You know, I've gotta say,
seeing you with Andrea
and that little boy...
[CHUCKLES]
It was nice.
Yeah. It's good, right?
Yeah.
[CHUCKLES]
And the way
she looks at you...
Oh-ho.
You think?
Oh, definitely.
[CHUCKLES]
So, is it, um...
Is it moving
in any
particular direction?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe. Yeah. You know,
sometimes I think,
you know,
if it feels right, then...
If it feels right,
it feels right.
Sometimes you just
gotta listen to your gut.
I mean, instant family.
What more
can you ask, right?
Absolutely.
MOE:
Cut the cards.
Have you thought about
what your plan is?
You know,
vis-a-vis honesty?
You mean how much
she knows about this?
Mmm.
Um...
[MUTES TV]
She doesn't
know anything.
I mean, you know,
she's not stupid.
She knows
I'm into something,
but she could make
a pretty good guess.
But I never
told her anything.
I'm not gonna.
Okay.
I mean it.
I know you do.
Jesse, I can't
pretend that this
doesn't affect me. It does.
But with everything
that we've been through,
the two of us...
This has to be
your decision.
I mean,
you've earned that.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Secrets create barriers
between people.
I'm speaking
from experience,
believe me.
All that you've done,
it's a part of you, and...
I mean, if you choose
to spend the rest of
your life with this person,
then you'll have to decide
how much
you'll share with her.
Meaning what?
Like everything?
Like Gale?
I'm just trying to say
that I trust you,
and I know
you'll make the right call.
If she loves you,
she'll understand.
[TV SOUND AUDIBLE]
They're leaving streaks.
This more ethnic-looking one,
he's doing a great job.
But the other one
is going back and forth
like he's
scrubbing a wall.
They have to go
in circles,
or you're going
to leave streaks.
That's pretty basic, right?
Uh, I don't mean
to tell you your business.
It's just...
It's simple
quality control.
So, I've got
some good news.
Guess what.
What?
No, really.
I want you to guess.
Marie, I really...
Okay.
Hank's back at work.
That's wonderful.
Yeah.
Sure, they love him now,
but where were they
when he needed them?
Merkert and all the rest,
they just about laughed him
out of the office
when he told them
about that chicken man.
As far as I'm concerned,
too little too late.
If it were me,
I'd tell them all
to go to hell.
Do I sound bitter?
But it's...
It's what he wants, right?
Yeah, it's doing him good.
I mean, his PT
is going gangbusters.
He's hardly using
his cane at all.
And thank you
for that, really.
I mean,
God knows where he'd be
if we had to go through
his health plan.
I'm just glad
he's feeling better.
So, speaking of which,
we have another
big event coming up.
Have you thought about
what you're gonna do?
Walt's birthday.
Whatever you need,
I'm here.
Mmm, yeah. I, um...
I don't think we're gonna
do anything this year.
What are you
talking about?
Of course we're
gonna do something.
Skyler, he was diagnosed
around his birthday, right?
I...
So it's been
a whole year.
Listen, I've had
my problems with Walt.
Why he wouldn't
come to the house when
we were all practically...
Whatever.
Water under the bridge.
But at this point,
every year is precious.
We are...
What are you doing?
Uh...
You don't smoke.
You haven't smoked
since college.
You can't be serious!
With the baby and Walt?
Skyler, you're not smoking
around the baby, are you?
And you can't smoke here.
There's gotta be some rule
or regulation, I'm sure.
You can't force your employees
to breathe secondhand smoke.
I know for a fact
that that is illegal.
Marie, shut up.
What?
I'm sorry. Please don't
speak to me like that.
I am simply
saying that you...
Will you shut up?
Hey...
Shut the hell up.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
Please stop...
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut up!
[CRYING]
JESSE:
That's a 5.23.
WALT:
5.23.
Last one.
[SCALE BEEPS]
5.26.
That comes to 49.27.
Good yield, right?
That is an excellent yield.
All right.
[GAS HISSING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Marie.
How you doing?
Where is Skyler?
In the bedroom.
She's resting.
Is everything okay?
Breakdown?
What does that...
What does that mean?
It means I don't know
what else to call it.
But I've never seen her
like that, ever.
Well, what did she say
when she was yelling?
Nothing.
She just yelled,
"Shut up, shut up,"
over and over again.
Did you know
she's smoking?
Occasionally, maybe.
It's not a regular thing.
Oh, I just wish
I had gotten your message.
"Messages," Walt.
Plural. I probably
called you five times.
I'm not leaving here
until I know
what's got her so upset.
Are you gambling again?
Is that what this is?
Please, God, tell me
the cancer isn't back.
No.
It's not the cancer.
Well, something happened.
I don't mean
to point the finger,
but this didn't just
come out of nowhere.
It's time to tell me
the truth, Walt. All of it.
I mean it.
You're right.
[SIGHS]
You heard
about Ted Beneke?
The accident?
What accident?
Oh.
Um...
A couple weeks back,
Ted took a fall,
a bad one.
He gave himself
a concussion,
and, uh, fractured
a couple vertebrae.
He's still
in the hospital.
He may never
walk again.
Oh, my God.
I... I didn't...
I didn't know.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Yeah.
But that couldn't
explain Skyler's...
Uh, yes. Yes, it could.
You do know, right? You...
You must know.
Oh, God.
She was
having an affair.
With Ted Beneke?
And listen.
It wasn't...
It wasn't
ongoing or anything, and...
Well, Skyler and I
have been trying
to put things
back together.
And then...
Then the accident happened,
and she got...
[SIGHS]
Look, Marie,
I'm begging you.
Please,
keep this to yourself.
I don't want Hank
to think less of her.
Or me.
When did you, um...
Was she...
I'm gonna go.
Okay. All right.
[SIGHS]
Thank you.
I'm sorr--
No.
[DOOR CLOSES]
MAN:
Ouch! That looked nasty.
Hey, you okay?
I'm good.
Really?
Yeah.
[VIDEO GAME CONTINUES]
[AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE ON TV]
[YELLING]
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
[LOUD BLAST]
Come on. You want
to fuck with me?
Okay.
You little cockroaches.
WALTER, JR.:
Dad, wait.
You want to play games? Okay.
I play with you. Come on.
Wait. Wait for it.
WALTER: This is it.
WALTER, JR.: Wait. Wait for it.
Wait.
You wanna play rough? Okay!
Say hello to my little friend!
WALTER, JR.: "Say hello
to my little friend!"
Nice! Just--
You like that?
Hey, Mom, uh,
feeling better?
Hey. Hey,
why don't you join us,
if you feel up to it?
We have popcorn.
I think there's
some pizza left.
If you're up to it.
Yeah, Mom. Join us.
Die!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
Oh, my God. Look. Look.
You whores!
WALT:
Oh! Everyone dies
in this movie, don't they?
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
Okay.
For you and you and me.
$367,000 each.
Ooh. Wait a minute.
After the dealers
got their cut,
we should be looking
at 1,379,560.
Mike, you're short.
You're almost
300,000 short.
You're forgetting
about the mules.
They get a flat 20 percent.
The what?
The drivers.
They're the ones
that take the product
from us to the dealers.
And so, transportation
is worth 20%?
They're taking a risk.
$275,000 worth of risk?
Wow.
What did Gus
pay his mules?
Gustavo Fring
didn't use mules.
He didn't need them.
He spent 20 years
building his own distribution.
He had 16 refrigerator trucks
running his product.
And do you know
where they are now?
Government impound.
You don't like paying 20
percent?
Maybe you shouldn't have
killed the guy.
Hey, hey, hey.
There's still over
a million bucks
here, all right?
That's for one cook.
And since you're putting on
the green eyeshade,
my supplier and I
came to an agreement.
The methylamine
was free this time.
But brace yourself,
because the next barrel
is gonna cost big.
Can we continue,
or you got anymore
burning questions?
Okay, kid.
You fronted us 120
to get us going.
So that's 40
from him and me.
120.
Yes. Thank you, Jesse.
Okay.
Now, Ira gets 110
for our piece of the business
and 25 per cook.
That is 45
from each of us.
Ira's guys get
10 each per cook.
Goodman's cut,
18,000 from each.
Legacy cost, $351,000.
That's 117,000 each.
"Legacy cost"?
I got nine guys.
You don't know them,
but they were part
of the previous operation,
and they know a lot.
And right now,
some of them are in jail
and more will be soon.
The feds rico-ed
their hazard pay,
so we are gonna
make 'em whole.
"We are gonna
make them whole"?
What is this "we"?
These were Gus's
employees, not ours.
They might have been
Gus's employees,
but they're my guys.
So what are they doing
to further our interests?
The cops are looking
at them very closely.
We don't want them
furthering our interests.
So we are
paying them, why?
Because it's what you do.
Oh.
It's what you do.
[CHUCKLES]
My guys are keeping
their mouths shut.
We make 'em whole.
One hand washes the other.
It's as simple as that.
Huh.
It sounds like
a simple shakedown,
simple as that.
We're paying
for their silence.
That's blackmail.
Business is my end.
This is business.
End of story.
This is your problem.
It should come
out of your end.
Hey. Hey.
Just take it out of mine.
All right?
Go for it.
I don't care.
Just take it.
Well, Jesse, thank you,
but no.
I'll pay my share.
Go ahead.
[SIGHS]
Let me
tell you something.
This...
is how it's gonna be
from here on out.
My guys are
an ongoing expenditure,
so you best get yourself
comfortable with it.
137,000.
[LAUGHS]
That's less
than with Fring.
Listen, Walter.
Just because
you shot Jesse James
don't make you
Jesse James.
MIKE:
Tomorrow.
How are
you feeling?
Okay, I guess.
Broke it off
with Andrea.
I had to.
She's gonna tell Brock.
I'm still gonna take
care of the rent and stuff.
It's the right thing to do,
but, you know...
I meant this.
How are you feeling
about the money?
You're looking
at it wrong.
When we worked for Gus,
we were cooking
200 pounds a week.
This last batch
was great,
but we didn't even
crack 50 pounds.
We maybe cleared less money,
but we got a bigger piece
of the pie.
It's like you said,
we're owners,
not employees.
I've been thinking
about Victor.
Yeah?
Yeah.
All this time,
I was sure that
Gus did what he did,
to send me a message.
Maybe there's
another reason.
Like what?
Victor trying to cook
that batch on his own?
Taking liberties
that weren't his to take?
Maybe he flew
too close to the sun,
got his throat cut.
[METAL DOOR WHIRRING]
[♪♪♪]