JESSE: There.
That's them.
(SIGHS)
Your play, Walter.
You're on your own.
Looks like you're
about 1,000 gallons
light here, Mike.
Where's the juice?
The methylamine
isn't coming.
Why is that?
And who the hell
are you?
I'm the man
who's keeping it.
What the hell's this?
We had an agreement, right?
We got our deal.
So where's the tank, Mike?
Mike doesn't know
where it is.
Only I do.
And you're dealing
with me now, not him.
Why don't you just cut
to what it is you want,
or what you think
is gonna happen here,
all right?
'Cause we're gonna get
what we came for.
That 1,000 gallons
of methylamine
is worth more in my hands
than it is in yours
or anyone else's,
for that matter.
But I need
distribution.
(CHUCKLES)
Distribution.
That's right.
So if you agree
to give up your cook
and sell
my product instead,
I'll give you 35 percent
of the take.
35 percent? Wow.
Are you kidding me?
35... Mike, please
tell me this is a joke.
You know how far
we had to stick our necks out
to get our hands on this cash?
And why the hell
would we want you?
You realize we have
our own operation, right?
I know all about
your operation.
My partners here tell me
that you produce a meth
that's 70 percent pure,
if you're lucky.
What I produce
is 99.1 percent pure.
So?
So...it's grade school t-ball
versus the New York Yankees.
Yours is, uh,
just some tepid,
off-brand,
generic cola.
What I'm making
is classic coke.
All right. Okay.
So, um...
(CLEARS THROAT)
If we just waste you
right here, right now,
and leave you
in the desert,
then there is no more coke
on the market, right?
See how that works?
There's only us.
Do you really wanna live
in a world without coca cola?
My partner tells me
that your crew
switched to a P2Pcook
because of our success.
You dye your meth
with food coloring
to make it look like mine.
You already ape my product
at every turn.
But now...
You have the opportunity
to sell it yourself.
I need you
to listen to me.
We're not gonna
give up this deal
to be your errand boys,
do you understand?
For what?
To watch a bunch of junkies
get a better high?
A better high
means customers pay more.
A higher purity
means a greater yield.
That's 130 million dollars
of profit
that isn't being pissed away
by some substandard cook.
Now you listen to me.
You've got the greatest
meth cook in a,
no, the two
greatest meth cooks
in America right here,
and with our skills,
you'll earn more
from that 35 percent
than you ever would
on your own.
Yeah. So you say.
Just wondering why
we're so lucky.
Why cut us in?
Mike is retiring
from our crew,
so his share of
the partnership
is available,
if you can handle
his end... Distribution.
And if you give him
five million dollars
of the 15 million
that you brought today.
Just think of it
as a finder's fee
for bringing us
together.
We have 40 pounds
of product ready to ship,
ready to go.
Are you ready?
(CHUCKLES)
Who the hell are ya?
You know.
You all know
exactly who I am.
Say my name.
Do what? I don't...
I don't have a damn clue
who the hell you are.
Yeah, you do.
I'm the cook.
I'm the man
who killed Gus Fring.
Bullshit.
Cartel got Fring.
Are you sure?
That's right.
Now, say my name.
Heisenberg.
You're goddamn right.
(♪♪♪)
I gotta hand it to you,
Walter.
Hey.
I appreciate
the kind words,
but I'm out too,
remember?
I know.
We'll talk.
Maybe we should talk
about how and when
I'm gonna get
my five million dollars.
And we will do that.
Absolutely.
It's just, you know...
Jesse, just give me
some time here, okay?
I'll need a little help
getting things up and running
during this transition.
You can at least
do that for me, right?
Huh? Come on.
Don't worry.
We'll figure it out.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(TRUNK SLAMS SHUT)
Well, I guess that's it.
Parting thoughts,
of which I have two:
First, as I said,
I'll handle the legacy costs
out of my end
so you won't have to worry
about my guys anymore.
Second, the bug.
The DEA will do
a sweep.
Can't say when.
Could be anytime.
But you need
to get it outta there,
sooner rather than later.
All right.
That's it?
No "thanks for
the five million dollars,"
no "sorry for chaining you
to a radiator"?
Just get the bug,
Walter.
So, hey.
I guess, uh...
I guess I'll
see you around.
No. Don't think so.
When I'm out, I'm out.
Well, I'm out, too, Mike.
Kid...
Just look out
for yourself.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Are we good?
You tell me.
Okay, Jesse.
Back it up.
You're good.
Keep it coming.
Straight back.
Slow it down.
All right.
That's good.
Hey, Mrs. White.
(TRUCK DOOR OPENS)
Vamonos.
I wish.
All right. Let's get
this thing hooked up.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Walt...
What is this?
Do you really wanna know?
Why are you
hiding it here?
Don't worry about it.
Who are you
hiding it from?
I said,
"Don't worry about it."
From the police?
Or someone else?
Someone who would
kill for it?
Why don't you
go back in the office?
go back in the office
and let us do this?
We'll get it
out of your hair.
(CLACKING)
(RATTLING)
Oh! What'd you
bring me this time?
They're bacon
banana cookies.
Is there bacon in these?
Oh, my God!
Just bits.
Just little bits of bacon.
Just enough to make
those suckers really pop.
Dan, this is too much.
I'm not sharing those.
Bad office etiquette?
I don't give a crap.
They're mine.
Well, they're yours to do with
as you please.
Good, 'cause my husband's
not getting any either.
How is Mickey?
Don't get me started.
He wants to buy a boat.
I can't even get him
to start the lawnmower,
and he wants
to buy a boat.
Oh, I don't know.
A boat might be nice.
A little one, maybe.
Oh, please. Where would
you even take a boat?
All the way down
to Elephant Butte?
Or Caballo.
It's beautiful down there.
You can even leave it
at the lake
if you don't want
to haul it every time.
We are not buying a boat.
I'll tell you that
right now.
And the last one is 545.
569.
Aw, dang it.
I almost got them
all that time.
Very good.
But actually,
I've got an extra one
for you this week...
603.
603. Where is that?
Right down there.
Ah.
All right.
I'll let you get to it.
Thanks, Dot.
Young Kaylee's gonna need
a second safety deposit box
if you decide to leave
one more dollar to her.
Mm.
How's the rest of it?
Oh, it's empty,
as usual.
The families
are pretty reliable
with the pickups.
Nobody complaining
about wanting it
all at once?
Nah, they get it.
Slow and steady
wins the race.
So I guess this is it
for a while?
Mm.
Don't worry
about the families.
They'll keep getting
their deliveries.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(HANK ON SPEAKER DEVICE)
I know times are tight,
but it's for the kids,
and your sponsorship
would sure be appreciated.
Yeah. We have
a, um, silver level,
but the gold
and platinum levels
really get
your name out there
on the banners
and t-shirts.
Sure. No.
No, that's not a problem.
No, you call me directly
if things change,
you hear?
(CLICK)
(SIGHS) Gomie,
take a brick to my head
if I ever have to make
another fun run call.
I'm done.
What's up?
Why you smiling?
GOMEZ:
'Cause the Ehrmantraut
warrant just came in.
Oh, baby,
now we're talking.
How quick can you get
your group together?
Two, three hours.
Make it two.
We're gonna nail
that son of a bi...
(WATER SPLASHES)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(WHISTLES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN:
Police! Search warrant!
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING)
Police!
Search warrant!
MIKE: Coming.
Hold your horses.
(LOCK CLICKS)
Search warrant.
Police!
Search warrant!
How's that restraining order
working out for you?
Uh, if you want me
to read that,
I'm gonna
need my glasses.
MAN: Too bad
you had to make the trip out
from headquarters, Sergeant.
MAN 2:
From out of bed,
you mean.
When a cop kills himself,
they want a full report.
(MAN CONTINUES FAINTLY)
MAN 3:
A single contact wound.
Powder burn on his temple
and right hand.
Suicide, I think.
Tell the wagon boys
they can have him.
Yes.
WOMAN: (CRYING)
When I found him,
he... he was dead.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey! Perfect timing.
Just about to get started.
Uh, you know,
if you can get going
on that settling tank,
that would be
a huge help.
We left that stuff
in there too long
after the last cook.
Mr. White...
I mean way too long.
Now we have
a tremendous amount
of residue.
You know what
we need to invest in
is a power washer.
Mr. White,
can we just take a second
and talk about all this?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Yeah.
Um...
Uh, look,
you know what
I think we need
to talk about?
Is doubling down.
Doubling down?
Mm-hmm.
Cooking 100 pounds a week,
not 50.
As in starting
a new lab,
a lab that you'll run.
A cook all of your own.
Why not?
You deserve it.
You're every bit
as good as me.
Well, what do you think?
Mr. White, uh,
I think that nothing
has changed for me.
I just wanna
get my money
and, and get out.
Jesse, this...
What we do...
Being the best at something
is a very rare thing.
You don't just toss
something like that away.
And what, you wanna
squander that potential?
Your potential? Why?
To do what?
I don't know.
Well, think.
To do what, Jesse?
Well, I'll figure it out,
all right?
Look at you.
What have you got
in your life, huh?
Nothing. Nobody.
Oh, wait. Yes.
Video games and go-carts.
Mr. White...
And when you
get tired of that,
what then? Huh?
And how soon will you
start using again?
Look...
Look, I know
how upset you are
about what happened
to this boy.
I am just as upset
as you are.
Are you? Really?
How can you say that
to me? Jesus!
I mean, I'm the one
who's the father here.
What, do I have to curl up
in a ball in tears
in front of you?
Do I have to lock myself
away in a room
and get high
to prove it to you?
What happened to that boy
is a tragedy,
and it tears me up inside!
But because
it happened, what,
am I supposed
to just lie down
and die with him?
It's done!
It makes me sick
that it happened,
just like everyone else
who has died in our wake.
What Todd did...
You and I have done things
that are just as bad.
Yeah.
All the people
that we've killed...
Gale and the rest...
If you believe
that there's a hell...
I don't know
if you're into that.
But we're...
We're already pretty much
going there, right?
But I'm not gonna lie down
until I get there.
What, just because
I don't wanna cook
meth anymore,
I'm lying down?
How many more people
are gonna die
'cause of us?
No one. None.
Now that we're in control,
no one else gets hurt.
You keep saying that,
and it's bullshit every time!
No.
Always! You know what?
I'm done, okay?
You just
give me my money,
and you and I,
we're done.
Hmm. Okay.
Why?
Why do you want
this money?
Because it's mine.
It's my cut.
But isn't it filthy
blood money?
I mean, you're so pure.
You have such emotional depth.
No, no, no, no.
You shouldn't touch
that dirty money.
I'll save you
from that, Jesse.
Come on.
You want it.
You want it just as much
as I want it.
And it's not wrong
to want it. Okay?
So stay
and work with me,
and you can make ten,
20 times as much.
Whatever, man.
You don't wanna pay me,
I don't care.
Yes, you do.
It's on you,
all right?
I'm done.
No, you're not.
You're not done.
You're not leaving,
because if you leave,
you get nothing!
Do you understand me?
Nothing!
Jesse!
Budget for
the current fiscal year
for electronic surveillance
is 1.5 million,
on par with ATF
and the Marshal Service,
but still just a fraction
of FBI totals.
We're lobbying congress
for an additional 1.41,
but we're waiting
on action reports
(FADING OUT)
to demonstrate we're actually
getting worthwhile results.
Our undercover operations
reap the most successful
actionable intelligence,
if you refer to the chart
in appendix four.
If ASAC Schrader
can tell us about
the surveillance man-hours...
Hank?
Hank!
I think we're going
to wrap this up.
If ASAC Schrader
can stay behind
while everyone else
clears out.
Thank you, everybody.
You know no one wants
to see you succeed at this
more than me, right?
Yes, sir.
I know how good you are.
I wouldn't have
stuck my neck out
to get you here if I didn't.
But you're not knocking
down doors anymore, bubba.
You're in charge
of an entire district office,
and that comes
with responsibilities.
I mean, Hank,
basic reports
aren't being filed
in a timely manner.
I'll work on it.
It'll get better.
Yeah, it will,
because way too much
time and money
is being spent
on the Fring case,
a case which is
essentially over.
All this overtime
to surveil
Michael Ehrmantraut?
That's just money that could
be better spent elsewhere.
I understand,
but I'm not making
these choices lightly.
We've got increased reports
of blue meth on the street,
Fring's gang
is still operational,
and Ehrmantraut is involved.
It's that simple.
I believe you.
But so what?
It's one case
out of dozens,
and you don't play favorites
with it just because
it used to be yours.
I really think that...
Don't play favorites
with it, Hank.
You got a bigger
job than that.
I mean,
forget the financial cost.
I hear you're personally
serving search warrants
out in the field?
That was an error
in judgment.
Won't happen again.
You're damn right it won't.
I'm just gonna bottom line
this for you.
The surveillance budget
for Ehrmantraut is now zero.
We clear?
Sure. Thank you.
Clear.
Good.
We'll be in touch.
(KNOCKING)
Yeah?
Hey.
So, Ramey wanted
to catch up with you?
Talk sports and stuff,
I guess?
Yeah.
Something like that.
No more
following Ehrmantraut.
Not worth
the financial investment.
Well, it's not like
the guy's going anywhere.
He's not even bothering
to throw our tails anymore.
He's just living
a boring old-man life
like he has nothing left
to hide.
And none of Fring's crew
is talking?
Not giving an inch.
You sweeten
the pot enough?
Zero jail time
and an all-expense-paid
trip to Maui?
(CHUCKLES)
Not that, but close.
Nobody wants to bite.
Christ!
They're either the most
loyal crew in history,
or someone's
still paying them off.
You still checking
bank records?
No one living
beyond their means.
Nine perps...
All being represented
by one lawyer.
Not unusual
in a case like this.
Yeah, this guy,
what's his name?
Daniel Wachsberger?
He represents every one
of these douche-bags
except for Ehrmantraut.
Can we find out
more about the lawyer?
You want me to start
tailing a lawyer?
Like the shit
ain't deep enough
for you already?
Hey, Ramey said we couldn't
follow Ehrmantraut.
He didn't say anything
about anybody else.
Do it.
You're the boss.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
All right.
Shall we get started?
Now, I know
that most of this,
or all of this,
is gonna be new to you.
But, uh, did you
take chemistry
in high school?
Just basic?
No.
Okay.
That's all right.
As we go,
I'll be as detailed
as possible
without being
overwhelming.
Yes, sir.
Look, Todd,
I don't need you
to be Antoine Lavoisier.
Uh, what I do need
is your full effort
and attention.
Listen and apply yourself.
If you do that,
then we just might have
a fighting chance here,
okay?
Okay.
Well, here we go.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHATTERING)
Slowly. Steady.
(MUFFLED CHATTERING)
(MUFFLED CHATTERING CONTINUES)
The aluminum helps
speed up the delivery
of hydrogen chloride.
Gently pour it in.
No spilling.
(MUFFLED CHATTERING)
You're gonna like
the little Schticky,
but you're gonna love
the big Schticky.
For bigger messes
like dust bunnies
under the bed
or picking up after...
Now...
The CO2
freezes the liquid,
crystallizing it,
which gives us
our finished
methamphetamine.
(SIGHS)
Now all that's left
is to break it up,
weigh it,
and we're done.
Wow. This is, um...
This is complicated.
It's gonna take me
a few more times
to get a grasp on it.
Oh, yeah.
It'll take
a few more times.
I do all right?
You did fine, Todd.
You applied yourself.
That's as much as I can ask.
Now all that's left,
I guess,
is to talk money.
We can talk money
once I get this right.
(ZIPPER UNZIPPING)
Hmm.
Morning.
Guess what I have.
Cake pops.
They're balls of cake
on a stick.
Very nice.
Thank you, Dan.
See? I put little faces
on them.
Hey.
(MICROWAVE OVEN WHIRRING)
(MICROWAVE BEEPS)
All right.
(SIGHING)
(HUMS)
Mm.
I'm, uh... I'm working
with a new guy now.
And I think
that it...
I think it could
possibly work out,
because...
I'm trying, Hank.
I really am.
I'm trying,
but there's this...
(SNIFFLING)
I mean, it's like I don't
even exist to her.
Well, yeah...
(STAMMERING)
I mean,
I know she's struggling.
I know, but I... I...
I just don't know
what to do.
I mean, what can I do?
Such a mess.
(STAMMERS)
(SIGHS)
I mean, we...
Both of us... We...
We just have
screwed up so much.
I'm just...
(SNIFFLES)
I'm sorry. I don't...
Um, do you,
do you have any coffee?
Maybe I could...
Coffee? You bet.
Yeah. You bet.
What, you take, uh,
cream, right?
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
(IMITATES GUNSHOT)
(DOOR OPENS)
All right.
Here you go, buddy.
Oh, thank you, Hank.
Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry
to waste your time
with all this.
Ah, no.
(STAMMERING)
It's really...
It's...you know.
You know.
Yeah.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
Hey, could you excuse me?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Sure, sure.
Tell me
something good.
You tell me.
I sweated the guy
for 14 hours.
That should be
some kind of record.
Quit your bragging.
What'd you get?
He's gonna do it.
He's gonna flip.
He's willing
to give us Ehrmantraut?
(CHUCKLING)
What are you wasting
your time for?
Go throw a net around
that son of a bitch.
All right.
(SWING CREAKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
DAN: Mike, hey, it's me.
Can you talk?
I can.
Great.
Look, there's a small
situation with the money.
I don't want to do this
on the phone.
Are you available?
I can come by
in a few hours.
That's not good for me.
Where are you now?
I'm at the park
with my granddaughter.
Where exactly?
Palomita.
Oh, you know what?
I'm not far.
I'll come to you.
You just hang tight.
(CLICK)
(RINGING)
(GROANS) Yeah?
WALTER:
Mike, they're coming for you.
Right now. They're coming.
Slow down, Walter. Who?
The DEA.
The DE...
Somebody flipped.
They have, uh, some...
Some kind of
bank surveillance.
And something
about some lawyer.
Someone is talking, Mike,
and they're coming for you
right now.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(SWING CONTINUES CREAKING)
(EXHALES)
SAUL:
How could Mike use
that clown of a lawyer?
Dan Wachsberger.
(CHUCKLES)
He would've had better luck
with the law firm of Moe,
Larry and Shemp.
Always consult with me
before using outside counsel.
All right, Saul.
Enough, please.
Instead of just
sitting around here,
what can we do?
Besides pray that
he gets away?
I'm open to ideas.
Because if the DEA
catches up with him,
and he flips,
it's good night, John-boy.
No. No way Mike
would ever flip, okay?
No way.
(SIGHS)
Yeah, yeah.
Never say never.
This is the second time
the DEA has confiscated
his bankroll.
(CHUCKLES)
You know?
Jesus, fool me once,
right?
Look, he won't flip.
But his nine guys will.
(PHONE HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
(DRAWER CLOSES)
Hey. Whoa, whoa.
It's him.
(SIGHS) Uh, Mike,
uh, I got you on speaker phone
with the brain trust.
The what?
The, uh...
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Walt and Jesse are here.
I don't want Walt
and Jesse, Saul.
I want you.
I need your help.
What do you need?
I got a go-bag
at the airport...
Passports, money,
but there are eyes everywhere.
I can't get close.
I need you
to pick up that bag
and get it to me
as soon as possible.
Do you know how thick
the crap storm is out there
because of this?
I told you
not to use that lawyer.
He's a hack!
Shut up, Saul,
and get the bag.
JESSE: Hey, Mike,
I can get it to you,
all right?
Just tell me what to do.
No, kid. Not you.
I'm paying Saul.
He can do the job just fine.
Yeah, you're paying me,
and the DEA knows
I represent you,
so they're probably
sitting on my car right now,
hoping I do
something stupid.
Mike, I can do it, okay?
It's not a problem.
No, Jesse.
Jesus, I'll do it.
Besides,
you're out, remember?
Mike, tell me where
to get this bag.
(WATER SPLASHES)
(CAR APPROACHING)
Hello, Walter.
Before
I hand this over,
I need something
from you.
And what's that?
The names
of your nine men.
(SCOFFS) Why?
You're never gonna
pay them off.
What's the point?
The point is, Mike,
it affects me.
It affects Jesse, too,
and we deserve to know.
The only thing left
to do now is leave town.
You understand?
"Leave town." Wow.
Yeah, I just can't
up and leave,
like you, Mike.
I've got a family.
I've got people
who depend on me.
Yeah.
Goodbye, Walter.
You're welcome!
(SCOFFS)
I'm sorry, what?
I want those names, Mike.
You owe me that much.
I don't owe you
a damn thing.
All of this,
falling apart like this,
is on you.
Wow.
(LAUGHS) Wow!
Oh, that's some
kind of logic
right there, Mike.
You screw up,
get yourself followed
by the DEA,
and now, suddenly,
this is all my fault?
Why don't you walk me
through this, Mike?
We had a good thing,
you stupid son of a bitch!
We had Fring.
We had a lab.
We had everything we needed,
and it all ran
like clockwork.
Oh, my God.
You could've
shut your mouth,
cooked, and made
as much money
as you ever needed.
It was perfect.
But, no, you just
had to blow it up.
You and your pride
and your ego!
You just had to be the man.
If you'd done your job,
known your place,
we'd all be fine
right now!
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(QUIVERING BREATHS)
I just...
I just realized
that Lydia has the names.
I can get them
from her.
I'm sorry, Mike.
This... This whole thing
could've been avoided.
Shut the fuck up.
Let me die in peace.
(SOFT THUD)
(♪♪♪)