(FLY BUZZING)
(BUZZING)
Mr. White?
Hello?
(BUZZING)
Mr. White, the, uh,
car's been dealt with, sir.
No one tailed you?
No. I stayed off
the main streets
and kept checking, so...
Joe ask any questions?
I told him RV job,
just like you said,
and he totally knew.
It's pretty cool
the way they do that,
turn a car into a cube.
So, should we deal
with this other thing now?
(BUZZING)
(SIGHS)
Yeah.
Sure.
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS)
I don't want to
talk about this.
Okay.
It had to be done.
All right.
I need to talk to you.
In private.
So what's the story?
You get to Mike?
Mmm-hmm.
He get out safe?
He's gone.
(SIGHS) All right.
Well, what about
those nine guys in jail?
They got no reason
not to talk now.
So what do we do?
"We"? Who's "we"?
There is no "we," Jesse.
I'm the only vote left,
and I'll handle it.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(♪♪♪)
My client will supply
vital information
relating to the organization,
distribution, and production
of Fring's
methamphetamine enterprise.
In exchange, we expect
all charges to be dropped,
and Dennis not only
walks out of here a free man,
but also receives
blanket immunity.
(SCOFFS)
For what
he's gonna be furnishing,
this deal is plenty fair.
(SCOFFS)
Best I'd be willing to do
is queen for a day
and reduced charges.
All charges dropped.
Queen for a day
and a five-k.
That's the best
you're gonna get.
No way.
Guys, come on.
You can be
a fairy princess,
for all I care.
Where you going?
I'm going shopping
for someone
who can tell me something
I don't already know.
Hey, hey.
I got plenty
you don't know.
You seem
a little confused.
This here
is a buyer's market.
I got eight
other assholes
just like you,
four of them within
100 feet from here.
I also got
Dan the douche bag lawyer
who's gonna
give me the money
and Ehrmantraut.
So settle in, Dennis.
Enjoy your new home.
I'm gonna go
rattle some cages.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CLOSES)
So?
Maybe you should
order something.
Do you want a coffee
or something?
Not just now.
I think this would play better
if you ordered something.
I think this will
play just fine,
and I'm not thirsty.
So let's take a look
at the list.
Lydia, you've come
all this way.
You do have the list?
Yes, I have it.
Good.
It's just not
written down.
And why is that?
It's in my head.
Safer there.
I see.
Then I suggest
you pick up a pen.
Not just yet.
It was my understanding
that attending
to these nine names
was precisely
what you wanted.
Ten names now.
Ten, counting the lawyer.
Yes. Ten,
counting the lawyer.
So, what,
am I not tying up
loose ends for
our mutual benefit?
You're tying up loose ends,
and I don't wanna
be one of them.
Once I give you that list,
I've served my purpose,
and then maybe
I'm just one more person
who knows too much.
So, you put that list
in my hands,
and in your mind,
I immediately
just murder you,
just right here
in this restaurant?
No.
Right here in this
public place, immediately?
Not right here.
That is not what I...
Listen, Lydia.
You made me promise
on my children's lives
that I guaranteed
your safety.
From Mike.
You guaranteed
I'd be safe from Mike.
There's no way
he'd ever go for this,
you getting rid
of his guys.
You wouldn't be
doing this, the names,
if Mike were
still a factor.
Yeah.
That's what I thought.
What do you want, exactly?
Because if you don't want
to give me that list,
then I've truly got
no use for you.
I can grow your
business exponentially.
Just give me the list.
I can do that
by helping you expand
into a larger,
highly active,
highly profitable
marketplace.
What do you know
about the Czech Republic?
The Czech Republic?
Did you know
there's a higher
demand for meth there
than anywhere else
in Europe?
Five percent
of its 10 million people,
which is roughly
the population
of the southwest
from Western Texas
to Phoenix,
are using meth.
You keep
your market here,
but by adding
overseas sales,
you can more than double
your current profits.
And I checked.
The average purity
is only about 60 percent.
They've never seen
anything like your product.
You'll blow
their hair back.
Shipping internationally
seems like
courting disaster.
Not if you're madrigal.
Madrigal
is under investigation
by the DEA.
The restaurant division,
mostly.
We've got
46,000 employees
spread across
14 divisions.
And once Mike's people
are no longer a factor,
things should
tidy up nicely.
This is what I do,
you understand?
I move things
from point A to point B
all over the globe.
1.2 million metric tons
a month,
and all of it
right at my fingertips,
a laptop click away.
The Czech Republic...
Who's there
on the other end?
People I ship to regularly.
People I've worked
with for years.
They're professional
and very amenable.
I'm very careful
who I work with.
And if this is
such a slam dunk,
then why didn't you
pitch it to Fring?
I did.
He said yes.
We were in the final stages
of working it out
when somebody killed him.
You don't think Gus Fring
built his
distribution network
all by himself?
There are
considerable advantages
to diversification
of distribution,
like putting
6,000 miles
between you
and your product.
At 25 pounds a week,
I'm estimating you'll gross
about two million.
Give me ten pounds to start,
and we'll see how it goes.
All right.
Now, with Fring,
my end was gonna
be 30 percent,
which I believe
is more than fair.
Okay.
Trust me,
if you do this...
Lydia,
learn to take yes
for an answer.
Now, first things first.
Shake on it?
We're going to make
a lot of money together.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BEEPS)
Todd, I think it's time
I meet your uncle.
MAN: No iron pile.
There's too
many muscle-heads
flexing their shit.
Too many eyes.
MAN 2: Okay,
so no chow line, no yard.
Gonna keep it simple.
Pass-byes.
Yeah. Hallways,
shower room, cells.
The easy stuff.
MAN 3: I say
we go with a riot.
Our boys get it done
in a riot.
No, no, no.
No chaos.
I don't want
the goon squad rolling in
and stealing our shot,
you know?
This has gotta be
fast and quiet.
Just boom, boom, boom.
You know
what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Surgical.
That's what it's gotta be.
So how many guys
we got at MDC?
Three,
counting Shaddock.
And he makes
the schedule now,
so we can put who we need
where we need them.
All right.
So MDC's covered.
What about the rest?
We need G block
in Valencia, right?
Our guy's
on the night shift.
Have him pull a double.
Nah.
His supervisor's got
some hard-on about OT.
Have him switch with somebody.
I don't know.
Just get it done.
Regardless, you know,
we got enough guys
in Valencia right now?
Might have to hire out.
You high?
Mix blood with chuntaros?
No way.
Well...
There's no need.
We got enough.
Hitters ain't the problem.
It's that short
walking window after lunch.
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah.
It's gonna be tight.
Real tight.
You know,
I gotta be straight
with you, man.
Taking out
all these guys is doable.
But hitting them
in three separate jails
all within two minutes?
Whacking Bin Laden
wasn't this complicated.
(CHUCKLING)
Where do you suppose
these come from?
I've seen this one before.
I wonder,
are they all
In some giant
warehouse someplace?
Hey.
It can be done,
just not the way you want it.
It can be done
exactly how I want it.
The only question is,
are you the man to do it?
Figure it out.
That's what
I'm paying you for.
(CHUCKLING)
(SIGHS)
(TICKING)
(LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(CRYING OUT)
(DOOR RATTLES)
(BLOWS LANDING)
Aah!
(MEN GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(TICKING CONTINUES)
(ALARM BLARING)
(MEN GRUNTING)
(THUD)
(ALARM CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
What's happening?
Oh! Oh!
What are you doing, man?
Don't do this, please!
No, man! Help me!
Help me! Help!
Help me!
(TICKING STOPS)
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Excuse me a second.
Grab more photos, will you?
(INAUDIBLE)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yes?
MAN: It's done.
New details have emerged
in the spate of jail deaths
that rocked central
New Mexico three days ago.
As of yet, no names
of victims have been released,
but authorities continue
to investigate
what appears to be
a carefully coordinated
sequence of attacks
that occurred within minutes
of one another
Giddyap! Giddyap!
in three different
correctional facilities...
Ooh!
Is it okay
if I turn this off?
Oh, sure.
I don't want
the news on right now.
Hank just pulled up,
and he's not in the best mood.
Oh, all right.
Well, I'll get out
of your hair.
Okay.
Hi, honey.
Dinner will be
in about an hour.
And I thought we could have
that chicken that you like.
Or we could
order Chinese?
Sure.
There you go.
There you are.
Wanna play
with your toys?
I'll see you
in a little bit, okay?
See you in a little bit.
Hey, Hank.
I was just getting
ready to leave.
Want a drink?
Um, yeah, sure. Thanks.
Perfect.
Rocks, right?
Rocks, yes.
(HOLLY COOING)
(SIGHS)
Been thinking
about this summer job
I used to have.
Oh, yeah?
Back in college,
I'd spend my days
marking trees
in the woods with this...
this orange spray can.
Marking trees?
Yeah. Crews would
come in later
and find the trees I tagged
and cut them down.
First, you go in,
and you mark locations
for skid trails
and landings.
Then you choose
specific trees
all within
a selected grid.
(SIGHS)
Every day,
I'd go back,
hike in,
pick up
where I left off.
Oh. Sounds nice,
being out
in the woods all day.
Nah, it wasn't so great.
I got sunburned.
There were mosquitoes.
I just wanted
to make a few bucks.
Buy beer.
Been thinking
about that job
more and more lately.
Maybe I should've
enjoyed it more.
Tagging trees
is a lot better
than chasing monsters.
I used to love
to go camping.
(POP ROCK PLAYING)
(SONG CONTINUES)
(SONG FADES OUT)
This way.
Here, baby girl.
Come see your brother.
There you go, sweetie.
That's it.
Oh, my God!
Look at her go!
Good job!
WALTER, JR.: Peekaboo.
This way.
Here. Let's go see
your brother.
Let's get him.
Get him!
Where'd you go?
I can't see you.
There you are!
(CHUCKLING)
(LAUGHING)
You're really good
with her.
(COUGHING)
Come here, my baby girl.
You're gonna be a handful,
aren't you? Yeah.
Mama's gonna get
her exercise. Aw.
(SIGHS)
Hey, do you, uh...
You wanna watch a movie?
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Louis.
Uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
One moment.
Uh, nothing.
(CHUCKLES)
What's up?
(SIGHS)
Oh, well.
(CHUCKLES)
It's nice to see you
smile again.
I mean, you seem good.
Yeah.
I'm hanging in there.
To see you laugh
like that just now...
It's such an improvement,
don't you think?
I don't...
I don't really...
(STAMMERS)
We've been thinking,
Hank and I, that
it may be time
to take the kids home.
It's been almost
three months, right?
Almost three?
Um...
Does Hank not want...
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, god. No. No.
Hank's crazy for these kids.
You know that.
It goes without saying,
we love having them.
And we're always
here for you
and wanna help you
any way that we can.
But...
We're starting to worry
that maybe...
Maybe we're
enabling you.
Sweetie, you've had
a lot on your plate,
and you and Walt
have had a lot...
So much
to contend with.
And I'm so proud of you for
going to therapy, by the way.
You know that, right?
It can be so helpful,
such a good tool.
And I'm very,
very proud of you,
but I...
We...
Maybe at this point,
the best way
to help
repair the family
would be
to repair the family,
you know?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(WATER LAPPING SOFTLY)
Take a drive with me.
Walt.
This is it.
This is what
you've been working for.
I rented this place,
and I started
bringing it here,
because...
I didn't know
what else to do.
I gave up counting it.
I mean, I had to.
It was just so much,
so fast.
I tried weighing it.
I figured one bill
of any denomination
weighs a gram.
There are 454 grams
to a pound,
but... (EXHALES)
There's a variety
of denominations, so...
How much is this?
I have no earthly idea.
I truly don't.
I just stack it up,
keep it dry,
spray it
for silverfish.
There is
more money here
than we could spend
in ten lifetimes.
I certainly
can't launder it,
not with
100 car washes.
Walt...
I want my kids back.
I want my life back.
Please tell me...
How much is enough?
How big does
this pile have to be?
(SOFT WHIRRING)
(CLICK)
(MECHANICAL HUMMING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Ow!
Aw, shit!
(SIGHS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(KNOCKING)
Hi.
Hey.
Um, I...
I hope I'm not
disturbing you or anything.
I tried calling,
but, uh...
Yeah. No, I, uh,
tossed all my burners.
Oh. And you didn't answer
your home line, so...
It's disconnected.
Oh, um, unplugged,
I mean.
Did you leave
a message, or...
Uh, no.
So, what's up?
I was just
in the neighborhood,
so I thought I'd drop by
and say hello.
You, uh,
wanna come in, or...
Uh, sure.
Thanks.
You know,
I'd offer you a...
A beer or something, but...
No, no. No, I'm... I'm...
I'm fine, thanks.
You, uh, didn't
wind up moving, I see.
Didn't have to.
Saul told me
what you did.
Anyways, uh,
I'm not in jail.
You aren't either,
so there you go.
There was
no other option, Jesse.
It had to be done.
I'm not coming back.
I know.
So why are you here,
exactly?
(CHUCKLES)
It's funny. I...
I saw a bounder
the other day.
Bounder?
Yeah.
Our RV?
A bounder?
Oh. Oh.
Oh, you saw
the same one as ours?
Yeah. Well,
within a couple years,
I guess.
Early '80s.
It was certainly in
a lot better shape
than our old
hunk of junk.
A much nicer paint job.
No bullet holes
in the door.
Yeah. That thing
was a nightmare, huh?
Oh, it was primitive.
You know, whenever
I hit a red light,
I used to pray
it wouldn't
crap out on me.
Yeah.
And then, suddenly,
it would sometimes
have that...
That screeching sound
that just...
Out of the blue,
like we hit
a pack of cats.
Power steering belt.
That's what that was.
I always had this...
This whole system...
Strategy to not
let it idle too low.
Remember that time
we ran out of gas
coming back from a cook?
Ah, the gauge.
The gauge always
said half-full, so...
Yeah, you had to
walk three miles
with a jerry can
while I waited
on the side of the road,
praying the whole time
that no cop would show up,
no good samaritan.
God.
We had money.
Why'd we keep it?
Why did we have to have
the world's shittiest RV?
Inertia?
Yeah.
Inertia.
So, hey, um, you know,
I gotta get going.
Yeah. No, me too.
I'm just meeting up
with some friends, and...
I gotta get going
as well.
I left something
for you.
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(CAR DEPARTING)
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey.
I'm out.
MARIE: With some big earrings,
it could be really nice.
Perhaps some big hoops.
I feel like I just want
to mix it up
with my hair this summer.
You know, like color...
HANK: Yeah. I don't know.
WALT: Did you have
a coin collection?
I had coins.
...have the time
to do hobbies.
Coins and baseball cards.
Those were the ones.
You can play around with it
and take them in and out...
Not enough hours
in the day, right?
Not enough hours...
MARIE: My hairstylist told me
to take prenatal vitamins.
For your hair?
He said they work,
so I figure why not?
Oh, uh, Flynn,
could you put some more
sunscreen on Holly?
Yeah.
Is it over there?
Yeah, it's right here.
Okay.
...for a home brew,
though.
Papa-free.
That's good.
Although I don't know
why it would be bad.
Yeah. I know. Me neither.
Oh, do you...
I used to squeeze
lemon juice in my hair.
You remember that?
You wanted to be
a beach bum so badly.
I did.
Ohh.
You and your stiff hair.
(GROANING)
Stiff what?
Hey, hey.
I was interested
to see you get into that.
Borage oil
is supposed to be good.
It's like chemistry.
Is it really?
Better than flaxseed?
I don't know.
That's cool.
I like your style.
There is no Christmas.
Maybe I should
brew up a batch.
What do you think?
Ooh, schraderbrau?
Yeah.
I vote yes.
I second that.
Well, there you go.
It's unanimous.
Well, who am I to fly
in the face of
public demand, right?
(CHUCKLING)
All right. Hold on.
(GRUNTS)
Anybody, uh...
Anybody want anything?
Want anything?
No, I'm good.
I'm good, thank you.
All right.
Does it look glossier?
Do I have a halo?
I don't know.
How's she doing?
She's good.
Try not to put
any of that sunscreen
on her fingers.
HANK: "To WW, my star,
my perfect silence."
(CHUCKLES)
WW.
I mean, who do you figure
that is, you know?
Woodrow Wilson?
Willy Wonka?
Walter White?
(CHUCKLES)
You got me.
(♪♪♪)