[♪♪♪]
[LIQUID SQUISHING]
WALT:
Jesse?
Jesse!
Show yourself right now!
[♪♪♪]
[CAR ENGINE RUNNING]
[IGNITION BEEPING]
[BICYCLES APPROACHING]
[♪♪♪]
[WHIRRING]
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
I'll be in touch.
Okay. Hey, Huell.
Listen, I want you
to swing by the high school
on your way to Saul's.
I can't believe he would
go after my son, but...
You got it.
And Kuby's at the car wash,
right?
Parked right across the street.
All's quiet.
No Pinkman.
Okay. Just find him.
[ENGINE STARTS
AND CAR PULLS AWAY]
[PHONE KEYPAD BEEPING]
[LINE RINGS]
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Please leave a message.
Jesse, listen.
I mean, obviously,
you've changed your mind here,
and so thank you for that.
And I know you're angry.
I wanna fix this, okay?
Whatever it takes, all right?
We'll talk,
and we will fix this.
Until then, just...
Just sleep it off, okay?
And then call me.
Be safe.
How's it coming?
I replaced the doorjamb
and the striker plate.
Switch this out,
we'll be good to go.
Good.
Do you want separate keys
for the different locks
or do you want one working both?
No, no, no. No re-key.
Same exact keys as before.
Usually with a break-in,
people like to get new keys.
No, same keys, same locks.
The old keys
have to work here, okay?
Okay.
All right.
[WHIRRING]
Good.
Good. Good, good, good.
[SNIFFS]
Oh, no, no.
Hey, guys, guys, guys.
Cut that. Yeah, this...
That area's still pretty bad.
Right.
We'll have to
go over this a lot more.
We've made
three passes already.
Like I say,
gasoline's tricky.
No, no, no. The smell
has got to be gone completely.
My wife is coming home,
and I can't have
any odor, any stain,
any sign that anything
happened here.
Understand?
I-- I know.
This is short notice,
and I really
appreciate it.
Sir, we'd love to take
more of your money,
but you've got gas soaked
through to your subfloor.
Until you pull this up
and get new carpet,
new padding,
this is as good
as it gets.
[♪♪♪]
Is that gasoline?
Ask Dad.
Hey. Over here.
What happened?
What happened is
that I should sue someone.
That's what happened.
So I'm on my way
to the drugstore,
and I have to stop
to get some gas
and there is this
total pump malfunction.
You know what?
She shouldn't be in this room.
I mean,
this is supposedly green,
but you know how it is.
You can close the windows
in the nursery
because it's really
only out here.
This is as good as it gets.
So, uh,
pump malfunction?
Yeah.
I'm standing there
filling up like I've done
a thousand times before
and I hear a chunk.
You know, the pump's nozzle.
The metal thing.
The thing you squeeze?
I hear a chunk.
So I suppose, in my naiveté,
I took to understand
that gas is no longer
coming out of the nozzle
so I pull out the hose
to put it back and whoosh!
Yeah, I am suddenly
soaked in gasoline.
I mean, on my arms
and my legs and my groin.
So now I am in a panic.
I race home,
I run inside the house,
and I'm stripping off
my clothes as fast as I can.
I jump in the shower.
It's not until
after I get out of the shower
that I realize
my gas-covered clothes
have been soaking
in the living room rug
this entire time.
I mean, it's-- It's--
The whole thing
is just so stupid.
I could have rinsed off
at the station.
Halfway home,
I started to realize,
wait a minute,
there's a water hose
right there
next to the air pump.
You know, for tires.
Anyway,
so that was my day.
How was yours?
WALT JR.: Dad?
Yeah.
Please, can you just
tell the truth?
Tell-- What do you mean?
You fainted, didn't you?
Because you're sick again?
You were pumping gas,
and the fumes,
they made you pass out again.
Just-- Just admit it.
No, the-- No.
It was the pump.
[SCOFFS]
All right, I...
Maybe I did get a little
swimmy at one point,
but I did not faint.
Okay?
I'm fine,
and that's the truth.
However,
in the best interest
of all of our continued
good health,
I don't think
we can stay here.
I mean,
not until we get new carpet.
Yeah.
Uncle Hank and Aunt Marie,
they got plenty of space.
Hey, what about a hotel?
A hotel.
That could be sweet.
A good one.
I like the way
you're thinking. Yes.
Could be
a little family vacation.
Might be fun. What do you say?
Why don't you put
some clothes together?
Yeah. All right.
I'm sorry.
It's not my finest hour.
I'll go pack a bag.
Okay.
Think this'll leave a scar?
I never should have let
my dojo membership run out.
Jesus.
Jesse did that?
Yeah, but you gotta understand,
deep down he loves me.
So, where is he?
Still looking.
WALT: Where have you looked?
His place, his folk's place,
this Brock kid's place.
Crack shacks at Siesta Hills,
the Indigo, the Crystal Palace,
go-kart joint on Copper Ave,
AA meeting off the 40.
His buddies,
Beaver and what's-his-name?
Badger and Skinny Pete.
Yeah, no, he's not with them.
WALT:
They could be
covering for him.
I posed as a meter reader.
I put a bug
on the tall kid's mom's place.
For three hours straight,
all he talked about was
something called Babylon 5.
I checked with
my gal at A.P.D.
She said Pinkman's
not in their system
so the cops don't have him.
Yet.
Maybe he changed his mind
about leaving,
called your guy back.
Somebody misses
their first chance with my guy,
there's no second.
Well, keep looking.
What then?
What do you mean?
I mean, Pinkman's
like a bad penny.
Sooner or later,
he'll turn up.
I'm wondering what you
wanna do when he does.
Jesse is upset about the boy.
I just need to explain to him
why that had to happen.
Okay, but say, you know,
just for the sake of argument,
the kid's not in the mood
for a nuanced discussion
of the virtues
of child poisoning.
His plans are running more
towards stabbing you to death
with a pointed stick.
In that scenario, then what?
You have a suggestion?
We were wondering if maybe
this isn't an Old Yeller
type situation.
Old Yeller?
Yeah, Old Yeller was the best,
most loyal dog there ever was.
I mean,
everybody loved that mutt
but one day,
he showed up rabid,
and little Timmy,
for Old Yeller's own sake,
had to, uh...
Oh, you--
You saw the movie.
You're full of colorful
metaphors, aren't you, Saul?
Belize, Old Yeller...
Just brimming with advice.
Do not float that idea again.
Find him.
WALT:
Sorry. Ah. Sorry.
Room key wouldn't
let me into the ice room
so I had to go down
to the front desk.
But here we are.
Checked in on Junior.
Heh. Pay-per-view
and room service.
He's in heaven.
Hey, I thought you
were gonna take a bath.
How's Saul doing?
Saul? Goodman?
No idea.
No?
You were just out talking to him
in the parking lot.
I'm sorry.
Were you spying on me?
Yes.
And I feel just awful
about it too.
You know, I played along
with your pump malfunction
bullshit
because Junior
was standing right there,
but now I would like to know
what's going on.
First of all,
it's no big deal.
Coming here is just me
being overly cautious.
Jesse Pinkman, remember?
He came over to our house
that time for dinner, remember?
Well, he...
He got upset over this...
Something he thinks I did.
I did do it.
But I did it
for very good reasons.
And it's just--
It's complicated.
Wait, are you...?
Are you telling me
that he tried to
burn our house down?
That was...
probably, for a brief moment,
his intention,
but, obviously,
he changed his mind.
And how does that work?
Him--?
Him changing his mind?
Ah, God.
Look...
You've got to understand
that with Jesse,
there are emotional issues,
personal issues,
some drug abuse. But he has
always been
more of a danger to himself
than anyone else.
He has a tendency to
fly off the handle, that's all.
So he has never hurt anybody?
No.
I can't believe
you got her down so fast.
So...
what's your course of action
here?
Saul's guy, Kuby,
tracks him down,
which shouldn't take long,
and when he does, I'm gonna...
I'm gonna talk to him.
Make him see reason.
Talk to him?
Make him see reason?
So I'm clear,
these are just euphemisms
you're using here, right?
No.
What?
Wh--? What does that mean?
My God. I knew
this was going to happen.
I knew it.
I told you that someday,
someone was going to come
to our door and try to hurt us.
And now here we are.
No.
Jesse didn't go there
to hurt anyone.
He poured gasoline
all over our house, Walt.
He tried to set
our house on fire.
He changed his mind.
He didn't do it, did he?
What if he changes it back?
[HOLLY BABBLING]
Walt, you need
to deal with this.
How much have you had to drink?
Heh, heh.
Not nearly enough.
I don't know how we got off
on whatever it is
we're talking about here...
but, clearly, I haven't
explained the situation
well enough because this is
a big overreaction.
We all need to just take
a deep breath and calm down
because Jesse
isn't just some...
Some-- Some rabid dog.
This is a person.
A person
that is a threat to us.
I mean, my God, where we are
now with Hank and Marie
and that awful tape we made.
After everything we've done,
you can't just talk
to this person.
You're saying...
that I just...
What--?
What exactly are you saying?
We've come this far.
For us.
What's one more?
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[SNIFFS]
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
Jesse!
Stop what you're doing
and turn and face me!
[SNIFFLING]
You wanna--?
You wanna know what he did?
You wanna hear about it?
Jesse, put out the lighter.
He poisoned a little kid.
An 8-year-old boy.
Just because, you know--
Just as a move!
Walt's a bastard.
Secret's out.
We'll talk about it.
But I need you to
put out the lighter, okay?
Look, Jesse...
Jesse, I don't wanna kill you.
And you don't wanna be killed.
So put it out.
He can't keep
getting away with it!
He won't.
You really wanna burn him down?
Let's do it together.
[CAR IGNITION BEEPING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
You were following me?
Yeah. Since Goodman's.
Where we going now?
DEA. Downtown.
What, I'm, like, arrested?
Yeah,
you know how this works.
Be a good witness for me,
it'll go better for you.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, sitting around MDC,
waiting to be a witness
against Mr. White.
It's... Heh.
It's gonna go great for me.
So...
you're angry.
I can't sleep.
I'm not eating.
Last night,
I was online for six hours
looking up
untraceable poisons.
This close family friend
had been keeping a secret
from you and Hank,
and somehow this person's
secret became known,
and now you're sad
and hurt and angry.
I'm--?
I'm in the ballpark?
To be this wrong
about someone.
This off.
We all lead double lives
to some extent, don't we?
We all have our secrets.
Yeah. Not like this.
Not like him.
Marie, I think it's time
you filled me in
on some more details here.
Who and what
are we talking about?
I said I can't do that.
It'd be bad for Hank.
Our friend made that clear
in his little movie.
Those kids...
under his roof. That baby.
I'm sick
just thinking about it.
How could I have not
seen this?
If I weren't being such a...
idiotic-- Stupid idiot,
I could've--
We could have...
Blackjack winnings.
Nothing suspicious
about that at all.
Tell me about this movie.
Dave, can we simply
just focus on
my feelings here?
The details
don't really matter, do they?
There's nothing
to be done, okay?
He screwed us and he won.
Can we just...?
Can we talk about
something else, please?
Yes?
How's work?
Last week, you were upset
about the new parking rules.
Marie?
Saxitoxin.
Derived from shellfish.
Produces a flaccid paralysis
that leaves the victim
conscious through
a progression of symptoms.
Death occurs from
respiratory failure.
That is definitely
a contender.
Marie,
you're not ready
to fill me in here,
that's fine.
But I want you to listen.
There is no problem,
no matter how difficult
or painful or seemingly
unsolvable,
that violence
won't make worse.
I know, I...
Don't worry.
I wouldn't hurt anybody.
I just...
It just feels good
to think about it.
[DOOR OPENS]
HANK: Hey, babe.
What's the story here?
Oh, well,
something's come up.
I thought you might wanna
get out of the house
for a day or two.
You thought I'd pack up
and move out of my own house.
Why? What's going on?
Look, I don't wanna
get into it now.
But you know that thing
with Walt, there's...
There's been a development.
What happened?
Are you in danger?
No, no, no, not at all.
Just-- It's a fluid situation.
I think it might go a little
smoother if you're not here.
So I... It's gonna be great,
you know?
I booked you a spa package
at La Posada.
You can do
that river-stones thing.
Hank, what the hell
is going on?
Hank?
We have a guest.
[SNORING]
HANK:
He was a little keyed up.
Gave him a couple
sleeping pills.
Okay.
Okay, so listen.
I bring that kid in,
put him in the system,
Walt's gonna find out
five minutes later. You know?
My last 10 witnesses
died in jail, remember?
And I can't use a DEA safe house
without writing him up.
I can't risk a motel.
I know it sounds crazy,
but this is the best place.
For now.
Just a day or two, tops--
Okay, just answer me
this one question:
Is this bad for Walt?
Yeah. Very.
Good. I'm staying.
I'll heat up lasagna.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Phone's ringing.
[CHIMING]
AUTOMATED VOICE:
You have one new message.
WALT [ON RECORDING]:
Jesse, listen. Uh...
I mean, obviously,
you've changed your mind here
and so thank you for that.
And I know you're angry.
I wanna fix this, okay?
Whatever it takes, all right?
We'll talk,
and we will fix this.
Until then, just...
Just sleep it off, okay?
And then call me.
Be safe.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Hey.
What are you still doing up?
Couldn't sleep.
Ah. You and me both.
Here. Have a seat.
[SIGHS]
Everything okay?
Oh, yeah.
Just business stuff.
Going over some options.
You guys still think
you might buy another car wash?
Oh, uh--
Yeah. Well, maybe.
See how it goes.
How it goes now that--
Now that you're--
You're sick again, right?
No. That's not what I mean.
Hey. Told you not to worry,
remember?
How--? How can I not worry?
Come on.
You think I came all this way
just to let something as silly
as lung cancer take me down?
Not a chance.
I'm not going anywhere.
Should've brought
our suits, huh?
It's okay.
It's all right.
[WALT JR. CRYING]
I'll be up in a minute.
Okay.
See you in the morning.
[PHONE KEYPAD BEEPING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Would you like some coffee?
[SNIFFS THEN SIGHS]
Morning.
You want some coffee?
No. The lady, um...
I think your wife...
MARIE:
You take cream and sugar?
Uh-- Black's--
Black's good.
Thanks.
This is probably
gonna take a while.
Oh. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll run some errands.
Okay.
MARIE:
All right.
Uh... You remember Agent Gomez?
How you feeling?
Your head clear?
Yeah.
This--
This can't be what you mean
by burning him
to the ground, right?
I got stories
that'll make your toes curl,
but, you know, it's just
"my word against his word"
kind of stuff.
So, you know,
I don't really have any,
like, proof or anything.
Gomey, can you grab
the curtains over there?
There's a glare thing
happening here.
You know he's retired,
right? He's...
He's not even
in the business anymore.
So you're never gonna catch him
with a camcorder.
HANK:
We're gonna catch him.
We gotta do this first, okay?
Come on.
Just tell us
everything you remember.
Any business dealings,
any personal dealings,
any criminal activity you were
a witness or a party to.
Anything and everything.
Just tell us your story, okay?
[CAMCORDER BEEPS]
Start from the beginning.
When did you first meet
Walter White?
Right. Okay, uh...
I first met Mr. White--
Walter White.
--in junior year chemistry.
He was my teacher.
[DOOR CLOSES]
You believe him?
Yeah. I do, unfortunately.
And I hate to admit it,
but I think the kid is right.
There is no physical evidence,
not that I heard.
Yeah, well, no weapons,
no bodies, no working lab.
Just the word
of one nut-job meth-head
against
Mr. Rogers-Has-a-Lung-Tumor.
So do we take a run
at Lydia Rodarte-Quayle?
Vamonos Pest?
Follow up with
the Drew Sharp killing?
Where do we start?
I say we start with this.
WALT [ON RECORDING]:
Jesse...
I'm gonna be at Civic Plaza
tomorrow at noon.
I hope you'll give me
the chance to explain myself
and talk through everything
once and for all.
I'll be alone and unarmed.
So if you wanna come
and shoot me in the head,
that's up to you.
Either way...
I'm in your hands.
[PHONE BEEPS]
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Go and talk to that asshole?
You can't be serious.
Go and listen.
He wants to explain himself.
We put a wire on you
and let him explain.
So your plan
is to do his plan?
You seriously
think that this--?
This whole "once and for all
in the plaza" thing
is so he can talk to me?
Why not?
I-- I--
I can't believe you two.
The dude
wanted me out of town
before I came to
burn his house down,
and now I'm more
of a threat to him.
And he's got a zero-tolerance
policy on threats, you know?
If I go to this plaza,
I'm a dead man, is why not.
Hey, Walt's ruthless.
He'll do just about anything
to protect his interests.
I agree.
Except when it comes to you.
He cares about you.
Heh.
HANK:
Can't you see?
Oh, yeah. You mean,
when he's not ripping me off
or calling me an idiot
or poisoning people
that I care about?
Yeah, no, Mr. White's gay
for me. Everyone knows that.
No, I mean it.
Based on everything you told us.
Uh, he paid for your rehab,
ran over those two
drug dealers with his car.
Sounds like he saved your life.
Made you a 50-50 partner.
He didn't need to do that.
Yeah, he sort of did.
I'm the only one near
as good as him.
I don't know.
The way you tell it,
sounds like he's manipulating
you to stick around.
Like he doesn't wanna lose you.
All those numbers he runs on you
over and over, helping you
find the ricin cigarette.
Look how far he'll go
to show you--
To convince you
that he's not such a bad guy.
That's what this is.
What if it's about, um,
killing me, you know?
You know, getting me
out in the open,
hire some, uh--
Some clock-tower guy
or have me sit on a poisoned
needle or something, you know?
Nothing's gonna happen to you.
The plaza's one of the most
wide-open public places
in all of Albuquerque.
It's the middle of the day.
And Agent Gomez and I
will be right there with you.
Look, you two guys
are just guys, okay?
Mr. White, he's the devil.
You know, he is.
He is smarter than you,
he is luckier than you.
Whatever-- Whatever you think
is supposed to happen,
I'm telling you, the exact
reverse opposite of that
is gonna happen, okay?
Jesse, Jesse,
we're not brainstorming here.
This is not asking.
Unless you know
another way to get the man
or you wanna take your chances
with the banger boys
over in MDC, then this is it.
This is what's happening.
I gotta piss. Can I piss?
HANK: Yeah. Down to the left.
You got another SD card?
[SIGHS]
What?
What if the kid's right?
What if it's a trap?
The kid?
Oh, you mean
the junkie murderer
that's dribbling all over
my guest bathroom floor?
Well, then, he's right.
Pinkman gets killed,
and we get it all on tape.
HANK:
Remember, you're hurt, angry,
but you're here
for answers, okay?
But don't...
Don't push the questions.
Okay? Let's not get him
suspicious, all right?
You let him do
the talking, right?
Just relax.
That's what matters most.
Don't cross your arms,
if you can help it.
Pancho Villa, Salma Hayek.
[OVER RADIO]
You getting that?
Loud and clear, idiota.
HANK: How's it looking, Gomey?
GOMEZ:
No change.
He's just sitting there.
Are we doing this, or what?
Ready to kick some ass, partner?
All right. Time to go.
Okay.
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
[CHATTERING]
[BOTTLES RATTLING]
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
GOMEZ:
Hey, Hank, you got eyes on this?
What's with the kid?
He's just standing there.
What the hell is he doing?
[♪♪♪]
He's on the move now.
He's taking off.
I think he's running.
Oh, no, no, no, kid.
Come on.
[♪♪♪]
GOMEZ:
You got him?
He's at the pay phone.
Who the hell is he calling?
Oh, no, no, no.
Come on, kid.
No. Come on.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Nice try, asshole.
WALT:
Jesse, where are you?
I just wanna talk to you.
No. I'm not doing what you want
anymore. Okay, asshole?
[OVER SPEAKER]
This is just a heads-up
to let you know
I'm coming for you.
See, I decided that burning
down your house is nothing.
Next time, I'm gonna get you
where you really live.
WALT:
Jesse, listen.
Jesse? Jesse?
[CHURCH BELL TOLLING]
GIRL: Daddy! Daddy!
Hey!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
HANK:
Get in.
Son of a bitch!
Stupid, high little--
What the hell
was that all about?
What were you thinking?
Thinking there's another way.
What?
To get him.
There's another way.
A better way.
[SIGHS]
[PHONE KEYPAD BEEPING]
[COUGHING]
Hey.
It's Walt.
I'm okay.
I, uh...
Todd,
I think I might have another job
for your uncle.
[♪♪♪]