JACK:
How big's the batch?
TODD:
Should be about 50 pounds,
give or take.
Uncle Jack, that mask--
I think you should...
Mr. White said the fumes
aren't good to breathe.
Let me worry about
what I breathe, kid.
Just hurry this up
so I can grab a smoke.
Seventy-six percent.
Nice going, nephew.
Thanks, Uncle Jack.
Where's the blue?
JACK: Where's the what?
The blue color.
Does it come later,
when this hardens?
Where is it?
I am correct in assuming
this should be blue?
See, I'm thinking the headline
here should be "76 percent."
Yeah.
Whole lot more than it was.
That dude who looked like
Wolverine? He couldn't crack 70.
Fine. Yes, percentage-wise,
it's marginally improved.
And congratulations, Todd.
But blue is our brand,
all over Europe.
It's what our buyers
pay top dollar for.
If we're down a bit in purity
from the Heisenberg days,
maybe they'll let us slide on
that, but not if it's not blue.
I don't know. To my eye
it's kind of blue.
Yeah, a little.
It's bluish.
KENNY:
Todd, you're the chef.
What do you think?
Yeah, kind of.
If it catches the light
just right
I could see how you'd think
there's a touch of blue,
blue-green in there.
Aquamarine.
JACK:
Hell,
we'll put food coloring in it.
Make it any damn shade
you want.
Yeah, like they do
farm-raised salmon. Yeah.
I mean, Jesus, you ever see
how pink they make that crap?
Like, flamingo pink.
It sure as hell don't come out
the ocean looking like that.
JACK:
All right.
Let's make some money.
Here you go, Ms. Quayle.
Lydia.
Thank you.
TODD:
Is the tea okay?
I made it just like you asked.
LYDIA: Mm-hm.
You sure?
If it's too weak or something,
I can go put
another bag in it.
I'm sure.
Look, about the product...
I'm really sorry
about the color.
For a minute or two, it just got
a few degrees too hot
in the mixing kettle,
I think.
I might've just cooked
the color right out of it.
You burned it, like a cake.
Yeah, sort of, I guess.
But the point is
I think I can fix it
and I think I can bring
the purity up too.
I mean, I'm doing everything
just like Mr. White taught me,
so...
You know,
it's bound to get better, right?
I appreciate you making
every possible effort
because, as you know, my buyers
expect a certain threshold,
a continuity.
Yeah. Yeah, totally.
About your buyers...
I could ask my uncle to smooth
things over with them...
if you want.
I'll pass. Thanks.
I've put a lot of faith
in your abilities, Todd.
I believe in you.
Please do make
the cook better.
It's very important to me.
I've got
a flight to catch.
[RINGTONE PLAYING]
♪ Science ♪
Hello.
WALT: Hey. It's Walt.
Hey, Mr. White. How you doing?
I'm okay.
I, uh...
Todd, I think I might have
another job for your uncle.
Oh, okay.
You want me to set up a meeting?
I-- Yes. Please. Let's do that.
Any heads-up I should give him,
like...
which jail, how many targets,
stuff like that?
Mr. White?
Just one target.
Not currently in jail.
Jesse Pinkman.
You got it.
[♪♪♪]
I'm surprised you didn't
strangle him.
So now what?
Book him?
I'm sure the AUSA
will have plenty to say
about how to play him
against Walt.
HANK:
Knowing what we know
about how Walt deals
with rats behind bars?
Punk has to be safer
with the marshals
than out here
where it's open season.
Hm.
What does that mean?
What are you thinking?
The kid's got an idea.
What kid? That kid?
Timmy Dipshit there?
The one that screwed up
our sting? I'm all ears.
Just hear him out,
would you?
Okay, genius,
what's the idea?
You guys need evidence
to put him away.
Only he's too smart
to leave any out there, right?
GOMEZ:
So you say.
Well, I know some evidence
that greedy asshole
would never destroy.
His money.
You know where
he keeps his money?
No.
But I know someone who might.
Oh, hey. How'd it go?
Trailed him to the Dog House,
picked him up there.
Seemed to be
looking for someone.
Had a lot of questions.
No calls though, right?
You got his phone?
Yeah.
He's on ice?
Safe house off Rio Bravo.
We've got Van Oster
babysitting him.
Yeah. What about Van Oster?
Did he have any questions?
Probably, but he knows better
than to ask.
Good job.
I gotta tell you this up front,
Hank.
If this guy decides
he wants to lawyer up
I don't care
if you are my boss,
I'm gonna put
a stop to this.
He won't lawyer up.
What the hell, man?
You're up.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hey there. You mind
taking it outside for a minute?
No, sir. You got it.
All right, thanks.
Huell Babineaux.
Know who I am?
I'll take that as a yes.
Thanks for your patience.
As Agent Gomez said,
you're not under arrest.
Why am I here?
Well, you're here
for your own protection, sir.
How you figure that?
Well, we both know how dangerous
my brother-in-law can be.
Nice poker face.
Look, relax.
There's not much new you can
tell me about Walter White.
Multiple murders,
ties to a white-power
prison gang,
ran the largest meth racket
in the entire Southwest.
I'm not asking,
you're not answering,
whoop-de-do.
Let's cut to the chase.
We have a wire on Walt's phone.
We intercepted a call
between him
and a certain Saul Goodman,
Esq.
You know, your employer?
Anyway, in the call, Walt said
that he was going to, quote:
"Take care of one
Jesse Pinkman," unquote,
and that you were next
on the hit list.
That's why you're here.
Bullshit.
That don't make no sense.
I got the recording.
I can-- I can let you hear it.
Your associate, Goodman's
fixer-- What's his name?
Some carrottop
named Patrick Kuby.
Boston P.D. ran him out
of Beantown a few years back.
Came out here
for the sunshine.
Walt said he was gonna do
this Kuby guy
the same way he does you.
In fact,
Kuby's already missing.
Sorry to say, things are looking
grim for your--
Your redheaded buddy.
Believe us, don't believe us.
Suit yourself.
Whatever you do,
I would not call Goodman.
He sold you down the river
bigtime.
The hell you talking about?
Don't take it personally.
Goodman's next
on the chopping block
if he doesn't do
what White says.
To be fair,
your circus clown of a boss
did try to spare you for all of,
what,
about 15 seconds
before he decided
to help Walt track you down.
You see, Goodman's got
a trace on your phone
and as soon as you call him
Walt will find out
where you're hiding.
Then it's just a matter of time
before you end up like this.
Oh, man. Oh, man.
I swear to God,
I didn't know he was gonna
kill the man.
I didn't know
he was gonna kill him.
Relax.
If we thought you did,
you'd be in lockup
for conspiracy
to commit murder
instead of here
under our protection.
Tell us everything you know
about White
so we can get him
before he gets you.
Why would he wanna kill me?
I ain't do nothing.
HANK: Who knows with this guy?
From what he said,
it may have to do
with him tying up loose ends
regarding poisoning
some kid named Brock.
Or maybe it's because
you know where his money is.
I don't know where his money is.
That ain't what we heard.
You ain't listening
to the people in the know.
Me and Kuby rented a van
for the dude,
loaded his cash up
in a self-storage unit
handed over the keys to him
at Goodman's.
Who knows where he took it
from there?
A van, huh?
How much money we talking?
Seven barrels' worth.
Seven barrels?
When you say "barrels,"
you mean "barrels" barrels?
Barrels, man. You know,
plastic, black, 55-gallon type.
I got them at Home Depot.
Filled up every last damn
one of them too.
And where did you rent the van?
Lariat. The one
on Candelaria and Monroe.
Lariat on Candelaria?
Yeah.
Kuby rented the van.
Mr. White dropped it off.
He had us wash it good
before Kuby took it back.
Wash the rental? Why?
It was filthy, man,
like he went off-road with it.
After we had hosed it down,
he grabbed a shovel
out the back
handed over the key,
and that was it.
That's all I know.
All right, Mr. Babineaux.
Agent Gomez and I are going
to do everything we can
to find this son of a bitch.
Like I said, you're free to go.
But if I were you, I wouldn't
take one step out that door.
GOMEZ:
And remember, no phone calls.
Oh, actually, I almost forgot.
Uh, I took the liberty
of removing the battery
so Walt can't track you
by GPS.
So don't put that back in.
Agent Van Oster
will stay here with you.
You're in good hands.
He's our best man with a gun.
Don't discuss the case with him
because the less
you distract him
the better
he can protect you.
How long you gonna be?
As long as it takes
to keep you safe.
JACK:
So just one guy this time.
Not even in lockup.
Some former partner, Todd says?
Yeah.
So, what are we talking,
rat patrol?
Rat p--?
No, no.
Rat patrol?
No. No, he's not a rat.
He's just...
He just won't listen to reason.
Okay.
He's just angry.
He's not a rat.
JACK:
All right.
Angry non-rat. Got it.
How angry we talking,
by the way?
Like, Hulk angry?
Like, Rambo-James Bond
badass individual?
Not something you'd do yourself,
huh?
Jesse is like family to me.
Look, I want what you do
to be quick and painless.
No suffering, no fear.
Bullet to the back of the head.
Something he doesn't see coming.
I respect that.
There's too many savages
out there.
Let's just talk about
the money.
No, we don't want your money.
We want you to cook for us.
[SCOFFS]
You know
I'm out of the business.
Just a couple times to tutor
my nephew here, that's all.
Get him on track
to bringing the purity up.
Get the color right too.
Apparently that blue touch
you put on it,
it's all the craze
with those Slavic types.
So I'm told.
No.
Absolutely not.
Look, what was the price per
head last time? I'll triple it.
A drop in the bucket
compared to what we aim to earn
from the blue stuff.
Don't skimp on family,
that's what I always say.
You want us to do this job?
Do it right? That's the price.
One cook...
after the job is done.
Time is of the essence.
Do you understand?
Do him tonight if you want.
Just tell me where he is.
I don't know where he is...
but I know
how to flush him out.
You want string cheese or yogurt
squeezers with your PBJ?
Both.
I didn't hear you.
Both, please.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hold on, honey.
Hi, Andrea.
I don't know if you remember me.
I'm Walter White,
Jesse's friend.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, of course. Hi.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, hi. Hi.
I'm sorry to just barge in
on you like this,
but I was hoping that I could
have a moment to talk with you.
It's about Jesse.
Sure. I'm sort of rushing around
right now.
Wanna talk inside while I get
my boy ready for school?
Oh, well, yeah. If it's--
If it's okay, yeah, sure.
Thank you.
You met Brock before, right?
Yes. Yes, I have.
At Jesse's.
How you doing, Brock?
Brock,
he asked you a question.
I'm good.
WALT: Good.
Froot Loops.
That's good stuff.
So Jesse...
Yeah, I...
I don't wanna alarm you,
but I've been trying
to reach him for days.
I've stopped at his house,
I've left all kinds of
messages on his voicemail
and he won't return my calls.
I can't find him anywhere.
Have you heard from him?
No, not since the last time
he called to check on Brock.
That was, I don't know,
two weeks ago, maybe.
Andrea...
Jesse's using again,
and I...
I have a bad feeling
about this.
Have you tried
calling the police?
Or a better idea.
Jesse's lawyer's name
is Saul Goodman.
I have his card somewhere.
I mean, he may have ways
of finding Jesse
without getting him
in trouble.
"Better call Saul."
Yeah. I-- I did that.
He was able to verify
that Jesse's not locked up,
but, otherwise,
very little help.
You see, the thing is,
is that Jesse and I
had this argument recently.
And I won't bore you
with the details, but he's...
He's-- He's pretty upset
with me and...
And I'm hoping that's the reason
he hasn't called me back
instead of him being...
Well...
Well,
I'll try him right now.
I mean, if that's it,
he's mad at you,
maybe I'll have better luck.
That would be such a help. Yes.
What--? What--? What number
are you calling him on?
Um, his cell.
You know,
he recently got a new one.
And there. That--
That's his new number there,
the highlighted one.
ANDREA:
Jesse, hey, it's Andrea.
Your friend Walter
just dropped by.
He's here at the house
right now.
We--
We're thinking of you.
Call me back as soon
as you get this message.
I really need to hear
from you.
It's important.
Thank you, Andrea.
I appreciate that.
Well, I better--
I better be going.
You're welcome to stay a few
minutes to see if he calls back.
No, no, no. You're trying to get
your son off to school.
If he does happen to call back,
would you call me?
Better yet,
I've got your number.
I'll call you back, okay?
And thank you.
See you, Brock.
[♪♪♪]
[PHONE VIBRATES, BEEPS]
We on?
Yes. It should be any time now.
Copy that.
Remember, fast and painless.
And take him away from here.
I don't want the mother
or the boy to know.
You got it.
[CHIMES]
ANDREA [ON RECORDING]:
Jesse, hey, it's Andrea.
Your friend Walter
just dropped by.
He's here at the house
right now.
We-- We're thinking of you.
Call me back as soon
as you get this message.
I really need to hear from you.
It's important.
Nice try, asshole.
How'd it go at the rental place?
Van have GPS?
No GPS. Nope.
They used to have GPS
until about six months ago
when the ACLU or somebody
sued them
and they had to
get rid of it.
Well, that's it.
Game over.
Yo, man, you can't
just give up on this.
Who said we're giving up?
GOMEZ: What do you got?
Just thinking about
what Babineaux said
about the van being dirty
and the shovel
that Walt had with him.
I'll bet you 10-to-1
he buried that money.
No kidding. So what?
There's a whole lot of desert
out there.
How we gonna find
the right spot?
You said it yourself,
there's no GPS on the van.
Yeah.
But Walt doesn't know that.
All right.
Here's your change.
Oh, count it out, please.
Here.
Three. That makes 15.
Plus 5, that is 20.
Give this to your
car wash professional.
Thank you.
Say it.
Have an A-1 day.
Oh, you too.
Good.
Why--? Why do I--?
Why do I gotta say that?
Because it reinforces our brand.
So getting the hang of it?
It's-- It's pretty basic.
Mom, it's Saturday.
Can--? Can I go?
Go where?
Home.
Pick up a few things,
maybe chill for a little bit.
I'm sure the smell
is gone by now.
Why don't you just stick around
here for a while longer?
I need you.
Hi.
Who do I give this to?
You know what? I'll take care
of it. Excuse me, son.
That'll be 14.97, please.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Hey. How you doing?
You're on our billboard.
You're--
You're the lawyer guy, yeah.
"Better call Saul!"
[SKYLER CLEARS THROAT]
Okay.
So 3 makes 15,
and 20, 25, 30,
35, 40, and 10 makes 50.
Thank you.
I like your commercial.
What--?
What happened to your face?
Oh, this is a--
I guess you'd call it
an occupational hazard.
Thank you, and please give that
to your car wash professional.
Very good. Thank you very much.
Good to meet you.
Yeah.
Don't drink and drive.
Okay.
But if you do, call me.
Have an A-1 day.
Mom,
you forgot to say it.
Yeah.
Yeah, I did. Okay.
SAUL:
Make sure you get in there
between the cushions, all right?
That's it. Way in there.
Attaboy.
What the hell you doing here?
I swear to God,
the kid left so much
booger powder in there
my Caddy is a K-9 unit's
wet dream.
Is your phone broken?
All 200 of them?
Huell's gone.
Huell's gone where?
No idea. AWOL.
Nobody's seen him.
He's not answering his phone.
So, what about Jesse?
WALT:
He hasn't shown up yet.
He will, Saul.
He's probably high as a kite
and hasn't gotten
our message yet.
Or he got it loud and clear,
figured out it's a setup.
The kid is not as dumb
as you think.
Are you wearing
a bulletproof vest?
Did you miss the part about
my bodyguard has gone missing?
Look, I had him
watching the Dog House,
figuring the kid
might show up.
Next thing I know,
radio silence.
You're the math whiz.
Add up two and two.
Jesse is not on some
killing spree.
It's me he wants.
It's just me.
Well,
then where the hell's Huell?
Any news?
Not yet, but soon. I promise.
Have an A-1 day.
SKYLER:
Next, inventory lists.
These are the inventory lists.
Every day,
after close of business,
you tally the total
of every item sold
and you mark it
under the appropriate column.
So say we sold, I don't know,
10 pine-scented air fresheners.
You mark "10"
under this column
and then you subtract 10
from the stock column.
Okay? Why don't you try that?
[PHONE BEEPS]
[♪♪♪]
[PHONE RINGS]
Jesse?
JESSE:
Got my photo, bitch?
That barrel look familiar?
Because I just found six more
exactly like it.
[♪♪♪]
That big bastard
who works for Goodman,
I pistol-whipped that melon
he calls a head
till he gave up
what he knew,
which led me
to your rental van
which, it turns out,
had GPS.
How do you like that, genius?
Guess you didn't think
of everything.
Look, Jesse,
I don't know what you plan
on doing here, but--
Well, I'll give you a hint,
Walt.
It involves a couple of
five-gallon cans
of gasoline and a lighter.
No, no, no! Jesse, please,
listen to me.
No, you listen to me, bitch.
You get your ass out here
as fast as you can.
Yes, I'm coming. Okay! Okay!
And don't even think about
calling anyone for help,
all right?
You hang up on me,
put me on hold,
lose my call
for any reason,
as soon as you do,
I'm burning all of it.
All right? One big bonfire.
You get the picture?
I get it, I get it. Okay.
All right. You better hurry
because I'm burning
10 grand a minute
till you get here,
starting right now.
I said, I'm coming!
Don't you touch my money!
Fire in the hole, bitch.
There goes 10 G's.
Oh, nice orange flames.
No, no, no!
Jesse-- Jesse, please.
I'm dying. My cancer is back.
You're not hurting anyone
but my family. Okay?
I can't spend this money.
It's not for me. I won't be
around long enough to use it.
It belongs to my children.
Oh,
you're gonna talk about kids.
You're seriously
gonna go there?
I am sorry about Brock.
No, you're not.
I am.
You're not,
but you're gonna be.
Yes, I am sorry about Brock!
But he's alive, isn't he?
He's fine, just as I planned it!
Don't you think I knew
exactly how much to give him?
That I had it all measured out?
Come on!
Don't you know me by now?
I know you're a lying,
evil scumbag,
that's what I know.
Manipulating people,
messing with their heads.
Open your eyes!
Can't you see that I needed you
on my side to kill Gus?
I ran over those gangbangers!
I killed Emilio and Krazy-8!
Why?
I did all of those things
to try to save your life
as much as mine.
Only you're too stupid
to know it!
Jesse.
Jesse!
Jesse, talk to me.
Jesse, I didn't hang up! Jesse!
[♪♪♪]
Jesse?
Jesse, I'm here. Where are you?
[CAR DOOR BEEPING]
Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch!
[COUGHING]
No. No. No, no, no.
[♪♪♪]
[PANTING]
Come on, come on.
Yes.
[PHONE VIBRATES]
Yeah?
It's me.
I've got Jesse in sight
and he's coming for me
right now.
He knows I'm alone.
Let's go, boy.
I'm guessing he's got backup.
How many guys?
I do-- I-- I don't know.
Where are you?
To'hajiilee.
An Indian reservation
west of town.
Get a pen.
Go.
Okay.
"Thirty-four, 59, 20,
106, 36, 52."
Those are coordinates.
If you want me around
to cook for you
you get here now.
You got it.
As fast as you can. Okay. Wait.
They're coming.
Looks like there could be
three men total.
Wait a minute.
What? What is it?
HANK:
Stay in the car.
[WHISPERS]
Oh, my God.
Walter, what is it?
Walter, you still there?
Walter?
Walter, you got eyes on him?
What do you see?
Walter, talk to me.
Forget it.
Don't come.
What do you mean, "don't come"?
It's off.
Do not come.
HANK:
Walt!
Come on out!
I know you're out here!
It's over!
Walt!
Come on out, Walt!
Got him.
Drop it!
Hands up!
Walk towards me slowly!
Stop.
Turn around.
Lace your fingers
behind your head.
Walk backwards to me.
Stop.
Get on your knees.
[PHONE BEEPS]
How'd you like
my barrel photo, huh?
Took it in the backyard
by the barbecue grill.
You know, where we used
to cook out with the family.
Gomey here thought the dirt
might not match. But me?
I bet your greedy ass
would be so worked up
about the prospect
of losing your cash
that you wouldn't catch it.
Looks like I was right.
He's clean.
Yo,
I remember this place.
It's the very first place
we cooked, like, ever.
It is, isn't it?
Hey, what say you save us
the busywork, Walt,
and point out the spot
where you buried your money?
No?
No matter.
I'll get a search team out here.
We'll find it.
Agent Gomez, should we flip
a coin for the honors?
No way, man.
It's all yours.
Walter White,
you have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be used against you
in a court of law.
You have the right
to speak to an attorney
and have an attorney present
during questioning.
If you cannot afford
an attorney,
one will be provided for you
at the government's expense.
Do you understand these rights
as I have just recited them
to you?
Coward.
[SPITS]
[GRUNTS]
[YELLING]
Get-- Get over here!
Bring it!
Get in the truck, will you?
Bring it, bitch!
Put him in the car!
Come on!
HANK:
Get in the car! Hurry up!
Get in the car, kid.
Come on.
Gonna take him down
for booking, okay?
You should stay here till
I come back with a search team.
You got it.
I'd take the kid with me,
but they'd probably
kill each other on the way.
Congratulations, buddy.
Hey.
I'll call the tribal police,
let them know we're here.
Gonna make a phone call.
[PHONE DIALING]
[PHONE RINGING]
Hank, why is there what looks
like brains in our garbage can?
Hey, baby. I got him.
Dead to rights.
You got Walt?
Yeah.
I got him in handcuffs
as we speak.
Want me to wave to him for you?
Well, he's not--
He's not feeling too friendly.
Oh, my God.
You did it.
Thank God.
Things are gonna be a little
rough for the next couple weeks,
but they'll get better.
Baby, you okay?
I'm much better now.
I gotta go.
It may be a while
before I get home.
I love you.
I love you too.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Who the hell is this?
Tribal police?
Hank! Hank! Hank!
No--
Police! Drop your weapons!
Jack, don't do it!
Jack!
Drop your weapons!
You heard the man!
Put them down!
JACK:
How do we know you're cops?
Show us some ID!
Damn straight!
Let's see some badges!
Jack!
Jack, don't do it! Jack!
No, Jack, it's off! Jack!
JACK:
We'll give ourselves up,
you show us some badges!
Simple as that!
How about it?
WALTER:
No!
Jack!
Jack, it's off! Forget it!
[♪♪♪]