[BOTH SIGHING]
Yo, so, what's next?
We wait.
You don't got like
eight more anal things
we gotta do first?
The reaction has begun.
Yeah, I know.
So how long?
Well, if we had a freezer,
the condensed liquid
would cool more quickly
because, of course,
this is an exothermic reaction
which means
"giving off heat."
And our desired product is...
Put me into a coma,
why don't you?
What did you just say?
What? What? Nothing.
Huh.
No, no, no. Not in here.
Duh.
Like I'm an idiot.
Yeah. Like you're an idiot.
Dick.
[SIGHS]
[GRUNTS]
God. Jesus. God.
Shut up.
Oh, wow.
WALT:
Bogdan. Bogdan says I'm not
doing the receipts right.
Well, he's got a bug up
his butt.
He's got a stick up his butt?
He's got a bug up his butt
about the receipts, anyways.
So anyway,
he's insisting that I--
He's demanding
that I stay
and look over his system
and I cannot get out of it.
Yeah.
[KEYPAD BEEPING]
[SIGHS]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
WALT [OVER PHONE]:
Hi, honey. It's me.
Hey, you. What's going on?
Nothing much.
I, uh, was just,
um, calling to say
I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna be
late tonight.
Bogdan. He's got
a bug up his butt.
That's okay. I wasn't planning
anything special for dinner, so.
In fact, you could take pity on
us and bring a pizza home.
They're having a two-for-one
at Venezia's.
At this point, I could eat
a whole one by myself.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
I can pick up a pizza, heh.
Hopefully Bogdan
won't keep me too late.
He better not.
Trust me,
he does not want to piss off
a hungry, pregnant woman.
Ooh! What's that sound?
SKYLER:
I just sold
your favorite piece.
The hideous crying clown.
Wow.
Yeah, and I got 9 bucks
more than I paid for it.
Shows what I know about art.
Hey, what do you think
about Holly?
For the baby's name.
Do you like it?
I think I really like it.
Holly. Yeah, it's nice.
Let me think about it.
Just feels right, you know?
It's my new favorite.
Well, it's a front-runner,
for sure.
[JESSE GRUNTING]
[SIGHS]
Listen, I was thinking, um,
maybe we can have a little
family time this weekend.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You know, just take a drive.
The almost four of us.
Heh-heh-heh.
Maybe we can head up
the Turquoise Trail,
stop at Tinkertown, maybe
grab some lunch in Madrid.
Oh, my God. We haven't
been there in forever.
I know.
Yeah.
So why don't we just do that?
Take a little break?
Sold. Sounds fun.
Holly. It's growing on me.
Yep. Me too.
All right, well, I had better
go and get this in the mail.
Why don't you call me, uh,
when you're on your way home?
Will do. Love you.
Love you too.
[JESSE CONTINUES GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
[GUNFIRE]
[HANK GROANING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GRUNTING]
Ah.
JACK: Whoa.
Simmer down there, sparky.
What the hell did we
just walk into?
TODD:
Hey, Uncle Jack,
I don't see Jesse Pinkman.
He was right here before.
JACK:
Anybody got eyes on Pinkman?
MAN: No.
JACK: What do you figure?
He may be headed down
that gully there?
That's the way I'd go.
JACK:
Frankie, Lester, go find him.
Jack.
These guys are DEA.
[GROANS]
[GUN COCKS]
WALT:
No, Jack!
No, Jack! Jack! Jack!
No! No, don't!
Jack, don't. No.
No, Jack, Jack, Jack!
Jack, no!
Jack, no. Don't kill him.
MAN: Uh-Uh, back it up.
Don't kill him, Jack.
Get back here.
JACK:
The hell not? He's DEA.
No, ah, he's family.
Say again?
He's my family.
He's my brother-in-law.
JACK:
Didn't cross your mind
to maybe tell us
you had a DEA agent
for a brother-in-law?
Did you know about this?
I called you off, remember?
I told you not to come.
Well, it seems to me
we did you a solid.
WALT:
You weren't supposed to be here.
Too late now.
How's about you telling me
what was going down
out here? Hmm?
You and your brother-in-law
don't seem
to be getting
along too well.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't concern you.
JACK:
We just wasted his partner here
and he's wearing a bullet,
so, yeah, I'd say
it does concern me.
This is between him and me.
No cavalry coming?
No.
You bet your ass
the cavalry's coming.
No, no, no! Jack--
[GRUNTING]
Jack! No, the DEA
doesn't know about this.
Not yet.
Hank.
Nothing can change
what just happened,
but you can walk
out of here alive
if you just promise us
that you'll let this go.
Heh, yeah,
I thought as much.
Sorry, man. Just no scenario
where this guy lives.
No, no, no, listen!
I have money!
It's buried out here. It's...
[SIGHS]
It's $80 million.
Eighty million.
So that's what got
this party started, huh?
But this money of yours won't
do me much good in prison.
WALT:
You can go anywhere.
You can do anything.
Think about it.
You can have any future
that you want.
Jack.
Eighty million.
And all you've got
to do
is let him go.
JACK:
That's a hell of an offer.
What do you think, fed?
Would you take that deal?
It's Hank.
His name is Hank.
How about it, Hank?
Should I let you go?
My name is ASAC Schrader.
And you can go fuck yourself.
Hank, listen to me.
You gotta tell him...
You gotta tell him now
that we can work this out.
Please. Please.
What? You want me to beg?
You're the smartest guy
I ever met.
And you're too stupid to see
he made up his mind
10 minutes ago.
Do what you're gonna do--
[INAUDIBLE]
[WALT CRYING]
JACK:
Pretty specific directions.
Most people tell me
to be somewhere,
they say, "West on the 40,
this or that exit,
second gas station on
the left." You know?
This here?
This is a whole other story.
That fancy phone of yours,
where does it say
this is exactly?
Yeah.
Look at this.
They even brought a shovel.
MAN:
Jack, no sign of Pinkman.
[WHISTLES]
All right.
Says this is it right here.
Dig.
[MAN 1 LAUGHS]
MAN 1:
What's that? A barrel?
Couple barrels?
MAN 1: Jesus.
MAN 2: Hell, yeah!
MAN 1:
Oh, Jesus.
Would you look at that?
MAN 2: Hell, yeah!
MAN 3: Goddamn.
[ALL CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
What are you waiting for?
Yeah, boss. Hell, yeah.
Let me get on this side.
MAN 2:
Get that out of there, man.
[THUDS]
[♪♪♪]
[CHATTERING]
JACK:
Okay. Pull a barrel off
the truck
and load it in the Chrysler.
Seriously?
Jack.
That's like 10
or 11 million right there.
You sure you wanna do that?
You gonna make me
say it again?
Go, go. Chop, chop.
Jesus, what's with
all the greed here?
It's unattractive.
Hey. Hey.
I'm leaving you a barrel.
Boys are gonna load it
for you.
You got the keys
to these cuffs?
I'm sorry for your loss.
My nephew here,
he respects you.
He would never forgive me
if things went another way.
Also you caught me
in a good mood.
So here's what's gonna happen.
You're gonna get in your car,
and you're gonna drive out
of here, all right?
No hard feelings.
Understand me?
We square?
Hey, man, I gotta know
we're square,
or we're gonna have
to go that other way.
Pinkman.
You still owe me.
If you can find him,
we'll kill him.
Found him.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
JESSE:
No!
Get off me!
Get off!
[GRUNTING]
No, no.
[GUN COCKS]
Good to go?
TODD:
Hey, Uncle Jack.
Well, he was out here
with those feds.
Right? Working with them.
Should we maybe find out
what he told them first?
Because, I mean, he had to
have told them some stuff
that might not be
too good for us.
And I'll bet we could
get it out of him back home.
I mean, I can do it.
Me and him,
we got history.
And then, you know, we'd take
care of the job after that.
Works for me.
Work for you?
FRANKIE: Let's go, pal.
No. No!
No! No!
WALT: Wait.
I watched Jane die.
I was there.
And I watched her die.
I watched her overdose
and choke to death.
I could have saved her.
But I didn't.
[ENGINE REVS]
[CAR BEEPING]
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
[GRUNTS]
[SIGHING]
[EDDY ARNOLD'S
"TIME'S A GETTING HARD" PLAYING]
[WALT GRUNTING]
♪ Time's a gettin' hard boys ♪
♪ Money's gettin' scarce ♪
♪ Times don't get
No better boys ♪
♪ Gonna leave this place ♪
♪ Take my true love
By her hand ♪
♪ Lead her through the town ♪
♪ Say goodbye to everyone ♪
♪ Goodbye to everyone ♪
♪ Had a job a year ago ♪
♪ Had a little home ♪
♪ Now I've got no place to go ♪
♪ Guess I'll have to roam ♪
♪ Take my true love
By her hand ♪
♪ Lead her through the town ♪
♪ Say goodbye to everyone ♪
♪ Goodbye to everyone ♪
♪ Every wind that blows, boys ♪
♪ Every wind that blows ♪
♪ Carries me
To some new place ♪
♪ Heaven only knows ♪
♪ Take my true love
By her hand ♪
♪ Lead her through the town ♪
♪ Say goodbye to everyone ♪
♪ Goodbye to everyone ♪
[WALT COUGHING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Hi.
Hello.
That truck belong to you?
It does.
I'd like to buy it.
It's not for sale.
Hey, Walt, it's me.
Um, just thought
I'd try you again.
We were just wondering
when you thought you'd be back
so just give us a call
whenever you can.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey, Aunt Marie.
MARIE:
Hey, sweetie.
Haven't seen you for a while.
What have you been up to?
Oh, you know. This and that.
Your mom and I need to talk,
so thought I'd stop by.
Well, I, uh,
wish you'd called first.
This isn't the best time.
Well, Flynn looks like
he can hold down the fort.
Why don't
we go into your office?
I got it.
Okay, honey. Thanks.
Marie, I have nothing to say.
Well, I do.
So you can just sit there
and listen.
I got a call from Hank.
He arrested Walt
three hours ago.
It's over.
"Dead to rights"
I believe is the expression.
Hank and Steve Gomez
are working
with a former associate
of Walt's, Jesse Pinkman,
whom I know you know,
and Pinkman has supplied them
with everything they need.
Hank is booking Walt
as we speak.
And I, for one,
could not be happier.
I almost didn't come here.
Christ, I barely even know
who you are,
and I sure as hell don't know
if I can ever trust you again.
And then I think about
how you were so upset with Walt
and how you wanted
the kids out of the house,
and all of this
makes me believe
that there has got to be
hope for you
that whatever he did to you
can be undone.
All I know, all I have been
forcing myself to remember
is that you are my sister.
And so I'm here.
[WHIMPERS]
Marie--
Everything changes now.
And you have got
to prepare yourself.
Hank will help you as much
as he can. I know he will.
And I will support you
through this.
But I have conditions.
Give me every single copy
of that obscenity
that the two of you made
to discredit Hank. That DVD.
Every single copy.
You understand me?
Answer me.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Good.
Now dry your eyes
and get Flynn in here.
You are going to tell him
everything,
and I mean everything.
He deserves to know
the truth from his family.
Not a bunch
of uniformed strangers.
No. No.
No, he cannot know.
You tell him, or I will.
There's no way around this.
He needs to know,
and he needs to know now.
[JESSE WHIMPERING]
[THUDDING]
JESSE:
No.
[GROANING]
Look, I gave you
what you wanted.
Come on, man, please.
Hey, please.
I told you where
to find the tape, okay?
TODD: Yup.
Hey, just go.
Just go there. Just go
to his house and get it.
We're on it.
Get it!
No one else knows about it.
Just me and his partner.
Okay.
No one else knows, I swear!
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GRUNTING]
[WHIMPERING]
Let's cook.
You're completely
out of your mind.
It's the truth.
MARIE: It is, Flynn.
Then both of you
are out of your minds.
You're full of shit,
is what you are. Both of you.
If this is true, then how could
you keep this a secret?
I mean, why?
Why would you go along?
I'll be asking myself that
for the rest of my life.
So you're saying all this time
you were lying about this?
Uh, I mean, so you're
saying you're a liar.
You just admitted it.
So were you lying then,
or are you lying now?
Which lie is it?
Flynn, honey, your mother
is telling you the truth.
Right here, right now.
Believe it.
You know what?
This is bullshit.
Baby--
WALT JR.: I wanna talk to Dad.
Your dad's in custody.
You can't talk to him
for a while.
I'm calling Uncle Hank.
MARIE:
I've tried. He's not answering.
He's probably in the thick
of it with your father.
Honey, I know this is
a lot to process, Flynn,
but if you could just breathe,
just try to breathe,
and just trust--
Really? Really?
Try to breathe?
[DOOR OPENS]
Oh, my God.
[CRYING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
MARIE:
Go home.
Just take the kids home,
okay? Go home and regroup.
I'll stop by later.
[CAR BEEPING]
Flynn?
Could you put
your seatbelt on, please?
Please. It's not safe.
You're shitting me,
right?
If all this is true
and you knew about it,
then you're as bad as him.
SKYLER:
Whose truck is that?
WALT JR.:
Dad?
[WALT GRUNTING]
Listen, I need you to come
inside and pack right now.
Mom, Aunt Marie, they said
that you were arrested?
No, just--
You're some kind of
drug dealer?
No, just come inside,
please. Now.
Come inside. Come on.
Go, go, go.
Dad, stop.
Just talk to me, please.
Our priority right now
is to pack.
Uncle Hank, they said
he arrested you?
I will discuss
all of this later, okay?
WALT JR.: Just tell me what--
Just listen to me!
Go into your bedroom now,
grab anything important.
You understand? Go. Now.
Both of you. Go.
Walt.
Why are you here?
Skyler, please, will you
just go get your things?
For you and the kids. Now.
This is our priority.
Hank had you in custody.
He wouldn't just let you go.
Where is he? Where's Hank?
I, uh...
I negotiated--
Negotiated?
Uh, yes.
What does that mean?
It means we're fine, okay?
We are. We're fine.
Everything is gonna be fine,
but we need to leave
right now.
All right? Can we do that?
SKYLER: What happened?
Where is Hank?
WALT JR.:
Why do we need to leave?
I need both of you
to trust me.
Right now, okay?
Please, just work
with me here,
and I promise I will explain
everything later, okay?
Where is Hank?
Skyler.
I have $11 million
in cash right outside.
We can have a fresh start.
Whole new lives.
All we have to do is go.
We have to go right now.
That's all we have to do.
You killed him.
You killed Hank.
What?
No, no, no.
SKYLER: You killed him.
No, no, no!
I tried to save him.
WALT JR.:
Uncle Hank is dead? I--
Mom, it can't be true.
It just can't be true.
WALT:
Just stop, please.
Everything is gonna be okay.
Everything's gonna be fine,
I promise,
but we need to leave
right now.
WALT JR.:
Dad, what's going on?
Talk to me.
Just stop for one second.
WALT:
Look, I told you
to get your things.
WALT JR.: Stop walking away.
WALT: There is no time.
WALT JR.:
Tell me about Uncle Hank.
WALT: No, just drop it!
WALT JR.: What's wrong with you?
WALT:
We're going.
We're going right now.
WALT JR.:
You have to tell me.
Dad, wait.
What happened to Uncle Hank?
What--?
Get out.
Skyler, I promise you,
we will figure this out.
Enough.
Mom, what are you doing?
Skyler, put the knife down,
please.
I promise you, everything--
SKYLER:
Don't say one more word.
Get out of here now.
Skyler--
Get out!
[GASPS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
WALT JR.:
Stop it! Just stop! Just stop!
[HOLLY CRYING]
WALT: Let go! Let go!
SKYLER: Get away from us!
WALT JR.:
Just stop! Stop!
Dad, stop it! Stop!
Mom, stop it.
Stop, Dad. Stop it now. Stop.
Stop! Just, please, stop!
Stop it! Stop! Stop it!
[GRUNTING CONTINUES]
[ALL BREATHING HEAVILY]
What the hell is wrong
with you? We're a family!
[HOLLY CONTINUES CRYING]
[♪♪♪]
We're a family.
[SKYLER CRYING]
WALT:
What are you doing?
Yeah, I need the police.
My dad, he pulled
a knife on my mom.
He attacked her.
He's dangerous.
I think he might have
killed somebody.
Yeah.
He's still here.
Yeah, he's still
in the house.
We're at
308 Negra Arroyo Lane.
308 Negra Arroyo Lane!
You've gotta come quick.
Hurry, hurry.
Oh, God, no, no!
Oh, my God. No.
Walt, no! Walt!
WALT JR.: Mom!
SKYLER:
Walt, please, no!
No! No! No!
[ENGINE REVS]
Walt, no! Let her go!
You can't take her!
Let her go, please!
Let her go! Walt!
Walt, please, no!
Walt, no! Walt, please!
Walt, no!
Walt, please, no!
Walt, please!
Please, stop! Walt!
[♪♪♪]
WALT:
Say, "Da-da."
Da-da. You say, "Da-da"?
There. Get rid of that
stinky old diaper, huh?
Don't be sad.
Where's your belly button?
There.
Now, don't you feel better?
You're all
nice and dry. Oh.
That feels good?
Oh, I know.
You were so wet
and so cranky,
but now you feel better,
don't you?
Next order of business is to
get you a brand-new car seat.
Won't that be nice, Holly?
[WHIMPERING]
Mama.
MAN:
Confirming the abduction.
Amber Alert. Holly White.
Female, 18 months.
Blond hair, blue eyes.
Was last seen wearing a pink
and white jacket, pink pants.
Abductor is the father.
He was in handcuffs.
Hank had him in handcuffs.
MAN:
Bald head, goatee,
gold wire-framed glasses.
[PHONE RINGING]
MAN:
Are you expecting a call?
SKYLER [ON RECORDING]:
Hi, you've reached
the White family.
Please leave a message.
WALT [OVER PHONE]:
Skyler, it's me. Pick up.
Pick up.
That's him. That's my husband.
I need you to pick up.
MAN:
Start tracing the landline.
The number's 505-177-8987.
I know you're there,
so pick it up.
Skyler, you hear me?
Need the location of
an incoming caller.
Answer the pho--
Walt, where's Holly?
Are you alone?
No police?
No. No police.
Where are you?
Where's Holly?
Walt!
What the hell
is wrong with you?
Why can't you do
one thing I say?
What?
This is your fault.
This is what comes
of your disrespect.
I told you, Skyler.
I warned you for a solid year.
You cross me,
there will be consequences.
What part of that
didn't you understand?
You took my child.
Because you need to learn.
You bring her back.
Maybe now you'll listen.
Maybe now you'll use
your damn head.
You know,
you never believed in me.
You were never grateful for
anything I did for this family.
"Oh, no. Walt.
Walt, you have to stop.
"You have to stop this.
It's immoral. It's illegal.
Someone might get hurt."
You're always whining
and complaining
about how I make my money,
just dragging me down,
while I do everything.
And now--
Now you tell my son
what I do
after I've told you
and told you
to keep your damn
mouth shut.
You stupid bitch.
How dare you?
I'm sorry.
You have no right
to discuss anything
about what I do.
What the hell do you know
about it, anyway?
Nothing. I built this.
Me. Me alone. Nobody else!
You're right.
You mark my words, Skyler.
Toe the line,
or you will wind up
just like Hank.
Walt.
Tell me what happened.
Where is Hank?
Please.
We need to know.
You're never gonna see
Hank again.
[WHIMPERS]
[CRYING]
He crossed me.
You think about that.
Family or no.
You let that sink in.
SKYLER [OVER PHONE]:
Walt.
I just want Holly back.
Please, Walt.
Just come home.
I've still got things
left to do.
[WHIMPERS]
[VOICE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN:
Hey.
[BABY CRYING]
[♪♪♪]