( majestic theme playing )
She's not just out of control,
she's out of her mind!
If you will explain
what happened, Lieutenant.
She hit me is what happened!
Your nose is broken
in three places.
I'll need to reset
the ethmoid fossa.
Try not to move.
We were having a disagreement
about the power grid.
She wanted to realign
the lateral plasma conduit.
I told her,
that would cause
an overload.
As usual,
she wouldn't listen.
So I told her to step aside
and let me handle it.
She pushed me away
from the console.
I pushed back.
Next thing I knew,
I was lying on the deck
with blood pouring
down my face.
Then what happened?
She said, "Sorry. Maybe you
should go to Sick Bay."
At least she gave you
some good advice. Now...
Ow!
Hold still.
Don't worry, Lieutenant,
I'll take care of this.
You keep that woman
out of my Engine Room
and everything will be fine!
Ow!
Where is Ms. Torres?
I've confined
her to quarters.
I would like her moved
to the brig
until formal charges
can be filed.
Formal charges?
Come on, Tuvok.
We're 75 years away
from the nearest court.
You're really going
to hold her in the brig
for that long?
The Captain
has the authority
to try Ms. Torres
here on the ship,
considering the extenuating
circumstances.
Well, I'd like to
settle this on my own
without filing charges
and without involving
the Captain.
She struck
a fellow officer--
that is a court-martial
offense.
She's a Maquis,
and in the Maquis,
sometimes you
have to push people
out of your way
to get things done.
Ms. Torres is no longer
a member of the Maquis
and with all due respect,
Commander, neither are you.
Allowing Ms. Torres
to get away
with a clear violation
of regulations
sets a bad example
for the rest of the crew.
It makes it appear
as though you are
showing favoritism
toward the Maquis.
Look, Lieutenant,
I don't have
to explain myself to you.
I'll deal with
B'Elanna personally
and then I'll
inform the Captain.
You're to drop this matter.
That's an order.
I will yield my authority
in this case to you.
However, I will make
a full report
in my Security Log.
You do that.
Sir, we heard
what happened.
What are they going
to do with B'Elanna?
I don't know yet,
but I'll handle it.
We heard that
Captain Janeway
is going to put her in
the brig for two months.
And that all the
Maquis are going
to be restricted
to quarters
when they're not on duty?
Not true.
We just want
you to know,
that if things do
get out of hand,
we're ready to back you.
What does that mean?
In case you want
to take control of the ship,
you have our full support.
If I ever hear you
talk that way again,
I'll personally throw you
in the brig for mutiny.
( breathing heavily )
( door chimes )
( growls )
Here.
What's this?
The medical report
on Lieutenant Carey.
Lieutenant Carey is an idiot!
When I tell you--
I don't want to hear it!
You might be interested to know
that the impact fractures
along his cranium
were pretty severe.
If you'd hit him
just a little harder,
you could have driven
some of those bones
into his cerebellum.
I didn't even come close
to hitting him that hard.
So on the one side,
I'm facing a Vulcan
who wants to court-martial you,
and on the other,
I'm facing all the Maquis
who are ready to seize
this ship over this.
You've turned this into
one lousy day for me,
Torres.
So, how long do I
have to stay in here?
Rest of the trip-- 75 years.
I've never found
your twisted sense of humor
very funny, Chakotay.
Or I could send you back to work
with the understanding
that you'll apologize to--
Apologize?
He was the one who--
Not just a simple apology,
a personal one...
over a hot cup
of pejuta.
Bond with the man.
I am not going
to bond with him.
You're going to need
support from people like Carey.
I don't need support
from anybody.
You are if you're going to be
Chief Engineer of this ship.
Right.
This is not
another example of my twisted
sense of humor.
But Carey's next in line.
You're a better engineer
than he is.
What does the Captain have
to say about this?
She hasn't said a word...
because I haven't told her yet.
( dramatic theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48439.7.
As we maintain a course
back to the Alpha Quadrant,
we're conducting
what would normally be routine
maintenance to the ship--
routine, that is, if we had
access to a starbase.
Engine efficiency is down
another 14 percent.
If we don't get more power
to the warp drive,
we're all going to have
to get out and push.
What about
alternative energy sources?
Ensign Kim, have you had
any luck getting power
from the holodeck reactors?
Not yet.
We tried hooking them
to the power grid
and we ended up blowing out
half the relays.
The holodeck's energy matrix,
it just isn't compatible
with the other
power systems.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain, if we relocate
all security personnel
to Deck 7,
we can shut down power
on Deck 9
and reroute it
to propulsion.
That would be inconvenient,
but acceptable.
Fine. Now let's move on
to the personnel situation.
We still have...
( door opening )
Sorry we're late,
but I wasn't informed
there was a meeting
this morning.
Oh, there don't seem
to be enough chairs.
Neelix, this is a briefing
for the Senior Officers.
I see.
Well, I...
I am the senior
Talaxian on board.
Kes is the senior Ocampa.
And I do know more about
this region of space
than any other member
of the crew.
We have some excellent
suggestions, Captain.
Very well.
You're welcome to join us,
this time.
Here you are.
To be honest, we could use
some excellent suggestions
right now.
I've been thinking
that you might be able
to convert one of
your lower decks
into a hydroponics bay
to grow your own food.
I understand that
the replicators are down
and that the emergency rations
won't hold out much longer.
What about Cargo Bay 2?
It was designed
for organic storage
and it already has adjustable
environmental controls.
When can you start?
Me?
It's your idea.
It's your project.
Right away.
I can do some wonderful things
with vegetables, Captain.
My feragoit goulash
is known across
12 star systems.
Okay.
The personnel situation.
We've managed to
find a replacement
for the Transporter Chief,
but we still need
an Astrogation Plotter,
a Chief Engineer,
medical support
personnel.
I've made a list
of several Maquis crew members
who would make good officers.
B'Elanna Torres?
She was the one involved
in that incident
with Mr. Carey.
That's right.
Just what job do you
think she's suited for?
Chief Engineer.
You're serious.
Very.
Regarding Sick Bay...
we still need a Chief
Medical Officer.
What about that electronic
man down in Sick Bay?
It is an emergency
medical hologram
and its abilities are limited.
It can only operate
within the confines of Sick Bay.
Not to mention
its lousy bedside manner.
CHAKOTAY:
Perhaps we should assign
somebody to train
with the hologram
as a Field Medic.
Good idea.
Lieutenant, I understand
you studied biochemistry
at the Academy?
Uh, only two semesters.
Close enough. You just
volunteered to become
a Field Medic.
Report to Sick Bay as soon
as we're finished here.
But, Captain-- Unh.
JANEWAY:
Stations, everyone.
( alarm blaring )
Report!
We're running into some kind
of spatial distortions.
Mr. Tuvok?
The distortions are emanating
from a highly
localized disturbance
in the space-time continuum.
Distance-- 20,000 kilometers
off the port bow.
All stop.
On screen.
Gravimetric flux density
is over 2,000 percent.
If I'm not mistaken,
we're looking at a type-4
quantum singularity.
( console beeping )
Captain, I am receiving
an audio transmission...
from within the singularity.
On speakers.
VOICE ( over speakers ):
This is...
ship...singularity...
( static obscures transmission )
I think I've found
the source of the transmission.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Does it look like any ship
you're familiar with?
No.
Nothing I recognize...
but then it's, it's
so hard to make out.
They may be trapped
in the event horizon.
Open a channel.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Starship Voyager
to the vessel near
the quantum singularity.
Do you need help?
Event horizon?
A singularity is a star
that's collapsed in on itself.
The event horizon is
a very powerful energy field
surrounding it.
Why, once on a particularly
dangerous trade mission
to the twin stars of Keloda,
I myself was almost
trapped inside...
No response to our hail,
Captain.
Can we tractor the vessel out?
No. The subspace interference
is too heavy.
Captain, we're less
than three light-years
from Ilidaria.
They have sophisticated
technology.
They might be able to help
and they're quite friendly...
most of the time.
No. It looks like
it's being pulled in
toward the singularity.
We have to get it out
of the event horizon.
Bridge to Torres.
We need a way to get that ship
out of there. Any ideas?
TORRES ( over intercom ):
I was thinking we could
remodulate a tractor beam
to match the subspace
interference.
It might be enough to cut
through the event horizon.
A subspace tractor beam.
TORRES: Exactly.
When can you
have it ready?
TORRES:
Two hours, maybe three.
Get right on it.
Use as many people
as you need.
Mr. Carey,
what do you think?
With the right field modulation,
it might work
but we'll need more power
to the emitter array.
Very well.
You're in charge, Mr. Carey.
Report to me
when the tractor beam is ready.
Aye, Captain.
Mr. Paris.
Hold our position here.
I'd like to see you
in private.
We have a problem
and I think it's
time we discuss it.
Captain, I appreciate
your concerns
about Torres,
but I promise you...
You don't understand,
Commander.
This isn't about Torres.
My problem is with you.
Me?
Let me be blunt.
What you tried to do
just now was out of line.
In what way?
When you decided
to call Torres in Engineering.
I've worked with her.
I know what she's capable of.
We needed an answer right away
and I knew
she could give us one.
Carey is the Senior Officer
in Engineering.
If you look at it that way,
none of my people
will ever have seniority.
That's the problem, right there.
They're not your people.
You're treating
the Maquis on this ship
like they're still your crew.
I'm doing everything I can
to integrate them into your crew
but frankly, you're not
making it easy for me, Captain.
I can't make it easy, Commander.
Surely you can understand that.
They don't have the discipline.
They don't have the training.
But some of them, like B'Elanna
Torres have the ability.
The Starfleet officers
on this ship
have worked all their lives
to earn their commissions.
How am I supposed to ask them
to accept a Maquis
as their superior officer
just because circumstances
have forced us together?
You're asking them to accept me.
You're qualified.
You're a graduate of the Academy
and you have
Starfleet command experience.
Permission to speak freely.
Go ahead.
I have no intention of being
your token Maquis officer.
Show me another qualified
Maquis candidate
and I'll consider him.
B'Elanna Torres.
Who cannot control herself
and who could not make it
through the Academy.
She's the best engineer
I've ever known.
She could teach at the Academy.
You're right, Captain.
I do consider these my people
because nobody else on this ship
will look out for them
like I will.
And I'm telling you,
you're going to have
to give them more authority
if you want their loyalty.
Theirs...
or yours, Commander?
I'm trying to help you.
I'm sorry you don't see that.
I strongly recommend
you get to know Torres
before you choose
a new Chief Engineer.
Permission to leave.
Dismissed.
( dramatic theme playing )
Computer, activate the emergency
medical holographic system.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Actually, there is no emergency.
I'm creating a hydroponics bay.
I was told you could provide me
with some nitrogenated
soil samples.
That's it?
I'm sorry if--
So it begins.
The trivia of medicine
is my domain now.
Every runny nose,
stubbed toe, pimple on a cheek
becomes my responsibility.
You are the only
doctor we have.
I am not just a doctor.
I've been designed
with the information
from 2,000
medical reference sources
and the experience of 47
individual medical officers.
I am the embodiment
of modern medicine.
( sighs )
How much dirt do you need?
Four samples
will be enough.
( sighs )
Now I know how Hippocrates felt
when the king needed
him to trim a hangnail.
You're very sensitive,
aren't you?
As a medical practitioner,
I require a certain
sensitivity
to properly
address a patient.
I'm talking about you
as a person.
I am merely a hologram.
Doctor, has your program
altered your appearance
since I came to Sick Bay?
No.
Why?
When I first came in
your head was at the same
height as this cabinet
but now you look at least
ten centimeters shorter.
I've just run a diagnostic
on my imaging processor.
It shows that I've been reduced
in height by 10.4 centimeters.
Sick Bay to Operations.
This is Kim.
The holographic projector
in here is malfunctioning.
Would you send a repair crew
down right away?
We're a little busy right now.
We'll get to it
as soon as we can.
It's just that I'm--
Kim out.
Well...
seems like a very busy day
in Operations.
I'm sorry
I bothered you with this.
No trouble at all.
Just turn off the program
before you leave.
What's your name?
What purpose would a name
serve a hologram?
I'd just like to know what
to call you besides "Doctor."
I guess they never thought
I'd be around
long enough to need one.
What's your name?
Kes.
I'm glad I could help you today.
Computer, end program.
( computer beeps )
( gentle theme playing )
( over intercom ):
Carey to Bridge.
The subspace tractor beam
is on line
and ready to go, Captain.
Acknowledged.
Mr. Tuvok, lock onto that ship.
Engaging tractor beam.
It's working.
The beam is penetrating
the event horizon.
Engineering,
check your power levels.
I'm showing massive
fluctuations.
Damn it! The new relays on
the power grid aren't holding!
We're being pulled
toward the singularity!
What's going on?
Power to the tractor beam
is down 80 percent.
The gravimetric force
of the singularity
is pulling us in.
Impulse engines, full reverse.
Disengage the tractor beam.
I can't shut it down!
The emitter relays are locked.
I'm picking up hull stress
all over the ship.
If we keep engines
at full reverse while
the tractor beam's engaged,
it'll pull the ship apart.
Cut the engines!
We're moving forward again.
Engineering, get that
tractor beam off-line!
Captain, I can shut it down, but
I'll have to get in there
and physically cut
the main power feed.
Do it!
Tractor beam disengaged.
Move us to a safe distance,
Mr. Paris.
Are we abandoning
the rescue attempt?
No, but we are going
to need some help.
Lay in a course for
the Ilidaria system.
Full impulse.
Have Mr. Neelix
report to the Bridge.
It looks like we're
going to follow his
suggestion after all.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You asked to see me,
Captain.
Have a seat.
I just want you to know
that I have personally gone over
every emitter relay again
and refitted
four of them myself.
No one blames you
for what happened.
Commander Chakotay
thinks very highly of you.
He's recommended you
for Chief Engineer.
Well, uh...
we've, uh, we've been
through a few scrapes together.
Do you think you're ready?
Ready?
Ready to be Chief Engineer
on a starship.
Well, I think I know my way
around an Engine Room,
if that's what you mean.
It's part of what I mean.
There's also the matter
of your ability
to command others.
I'm not sure
I'd be doing you a favor
by putting you in charge
down there.
There'd be a lot
of hard feelings toward you
from many
of the Starfleet people.
I'm not bothered
by what people think of me.
And the job requires knowledge
of Starfleet protocol,
experience with Starfleet
methodologies...
Listen, Captain
if you don't think
I'm right for this job
just say so.
I'll be honest.
I'm not sure whether
you are or not.
That's why I wanted to meet,
try to get to know
you a little better.
I've been studying
your Academy record.
Where did you get that?
Thanks to Tuvok,
we had the names
of your entire crew
by the time we left DS9.
Four disciplinary hearings,
one suspension.
You had quite a turbulent
couple of years,
didn't you?
Yeah, I guess
you could say that.
What do you think
the problem was?
The problem?
The problem was a system
that didn't give anyone
a chance to breathe.
We work under that same system
on this ship.
Then I guess maybe
this is just a bad idea.
Why did you quit
the Academy, B'Elanna?
I didn't want to have anything
to do with Starfleet then,
and I'm sorry
that I have to now.
( sighs )
DOCTOR (over intercom ):
Sick Bay to Captain Janeway.
Yes, Doctor?
May I request you activate
monitor input 47--
your emergency
medical holograph channel?
Of course.
I'm getting
a distorted transmission.
No. In fact, that is
how I appear at present.
I'm...shrinking.
Shrinking?
There appears
to be a malfunction
in my imaging system.
It's been reducing
my height
by five centimeters every hour.
I've been waiting all day
for repairs.
That is not, however,
what I am calling about.
Over the past three hours,
nine crew members have reported
unusual symptoms--
severe headaches,
muscle spasms
and sudden waves of dizziness.
All of this could be related
to the quantum singularity.
Quantum singularity?
It was sending out
strong spatial distortions.
They might have affected
the crew
and your systems as well.
You know, Captain,
if we were in the vicinity
of a quantum singularity,
I should have been informed.
You're right.
I'll look into linking your
program into the ship's data.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hello? Captain?
( door opens )
Hello!
Report.
It looks like we're running
into more spatial distortions.
KIM:
I'm picking up a highly
localized disturbance
off the port bow.
On screen.
Mr. Tuvok?
It is another type-4
quantum
singularity.
Physical and temporal
dimensions are identical
to the one
we encountered earlier.
Captain, according
to these readings,
we've returned
to our previous coordinates.
This isn't another singularity.
It's the same one.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Check the navigational logs.
Confirm our position.
Well, they show we've travelled
1.4 light years away
from the anomaly,
but I've confirmed our position
against the star chart.
We're definitely back where we
started. Doesn't make sense.
They can't
both be right.
We're either still at
the singularity or we're not.
Well, we can
see the singularity
so I tend to believe that the
external sensors are correct.
TUVOK:
That would imply
there was something
wrong with the warp drive
and the navigational logs.
Mister Paris, lay in a course
away from the singularity.
This time at maximum warp.
Ensign Kim, I want you to keep a
sensor lock on the singularity.
Verify that we're
moving away from it.
Engage.
( majestic theme playing )
Distance from the singularity
is 10 million kilometers
and increasing.
Warp engines holding steady.
All systems report normal.
11 million. 12 million.
( console beeping )
I don't get it.
Mr. Paris,
have we altered course?
No, we're still steady
on 310 mark 215.
Then something's
really wrong here.
It's ahead of us again.
Confirmed.
We're back
at the same coordinates.
All stop.
Ensign Kim,
transfer all the data
on the spatial distortions
we encountered
to my ready room.
I'm going to begin
my own analysis.
Commander,
have all departments
run complete
system diagnostics.
I'll expect a full report
from all senior officers
at 1500 hours.
Who will represent
Engineering?
Lieutenant Carey.
You should invite
B'Elanna Torres as well,
unless you've removed her
from consideration.
Fine.
( majestic theme playing )
The Captain says
she wants you
to attend the staff
meeting this afternoon.
Oh.
Well, I'll give you
a full report on what happens.
I'll be there, too.
Just remember, Torres,
I'm the Senior Officer
and I speak for Engineering.
Try not to say anything
unless someone
asks you a question.
1500 hours, Deck 1.
Don't be late.
( door opens and closes )
You should have broken
more than his nose.
I've taken a look
at every major subsystem
and there's no sign
of any trouble.
What about the
navigational array?
We'll have the results
in about an hour.
So, I hear there's been
some trouble
down in Engineering.
There was an altercation,
but it has been resolved.
Oh, that's not
what I hear.
I hear that the whole
department's up in arms.
That the Maquis
and Starfleet people
are almost at
each other's throats.
I will never
cease to be amazed
by the human capacity
for hyperbole.
The situation may be
characterized as tense,
but one could hardly say
that they are about
to become violent.
Well, I just hope
you're right.
I mean, things are bad enough
around here without... ow!
Are you all right?
Yeah. I just have this
splitting headache, and... ow!
( suspenseful theme playing )
I'd better get you
to Sick Bay.
Just dizzy. Can't-- Ah.
Can't focus.
27 other crew members
have now reported the symptoms
and yet, when I
examined each of them,
I couldn't find anything wrong.
I have no diagnosis,
no prognosis,
no recommended treatment.
I'll contact you when I have
something more to contribute.
And by the way, I am now
68 centimeters shorter.
I'd appreciate it if someone
would repair
my holographic projectors
before I have trouble
reaching my patients.
I've finished my study
of the spatial distortions
coming from the singularity.
I can give you a long, boring
analysis.
Suffice it to say, I don't
know what's going on.
The readings
are confused,
the data is contradictory.
None of it
makes any sense.
Anyone have anything
more constructive?
Ship-wide diagnostics
have revealed nothing
out of the ordinary.
I tried sending out
a tachyon signal,
to scan the singularity,
but all I got back was static.
B'Elanna, do you think
you can work with Mr. Carey
to clean up that signal?
Yes.
Good.
But it won't work.
I mean, it was
a good idea to try it,
but... it won't work.
You have another idea?
I was just thinking
about the problem
with the Doctor's
holographic projectors.
It seems like
the spatial distortions
might be interfering
with the projector's
phase alignment.
That was my guess, too.
If that's the case,
I could screen out those
distortions by setting up
a localized damping field
around the projectors.
Is our priority here really
the medical holograph system?
My point is that if
the spatial distortions
are also interfering
with the transmission
we received from
the other ship--
We could set up
a similar field
around our
external sensors
and communicate with them.
Exactly.
And they may know more about
what's going on than we do.
Let's give it a try.
Dismissed.
( majestic theme playing )
Emitters on line.
I'm rerouting
the damping field
through
the deflector grid.
Open a channel
to the other ship.
VOICE ( over speakers ):
This is... singularity...
Ramping up field intensity.
It's working.
We're cutting through
the distortions.
VOICE:
This is...
to the vessel near the...
Remodulate the EM band.
See if you can clear it up
a little more.
Compensating for
amplitude distortion.
VOICE ( less static ):
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Starship Voyager
to the vessel
near the quantum singularity.
Do you need help?
That's your hail.
I'm applying the damping field
to our visual scanners.
I'll see if I can clarify
the image.
It's the Voyager.
It's us.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( mellow theme playing )
Sensors confirm
it's definitely USS Voyager.
I've been hailing the ship
on all frequencies.
No response.
I don't think you'll get
a response, Lieutenant.
That message we unscrambled
is the same message I sent out
nine hours ago.
Could we have traveled
back in time
and met ourselves?
No, that's not it.
I think I have an explanation.
( majestic theme playing )
Think of it like this.
You're sitting
at the bottom of a pond,
which is frozen over
and you look up
at the surface and you see
a reflection of yourself.
Now you might think you're
looking at another person
sitting at the bottom
of another pond
looking back at you.
And in this case,
we'd be staring up
at the surface
of the event horizon
and seeing a time-delayed
reflection of ourselves.
Are you saying...
we're the ones trapped
in the singularity?
Unfortunately, yes.
You're right. It's the only
theory that explains
everything that's happened
to us. We've probably
been in this singularity since
we felt the first jolt.
PARIS:
Wait a minute, wait.
Wait a minute.
Let me get this straight.
We were cruising along
at warp seven.
Then we pick up a distress call
and moved in to investigate.
But now, you're saying
that the other ship
is actually just
a reflection of us
and that the distress call
is actually
just the Captain's opening hail.
But we picked up
the distress call
before she sent the hail.
How could we have been seeing
a reflection of something
we hadn't even done yet?
Am I making any sense here?
No, but that's okay.
One of the more difficult
concepts to grasp
in temporal mechanics
is that sometimes
effect can precede cause.
A reaction
can be observed
before the action
which initiated it.
So, what do we do to get out?
I'm not sure,
but I do know one thing.
That as we slide deeper
into the singularity,
the spatial distortions
are increasing.
According to my calculations,
within nine hours,
they'll crush the ship.
If your analogy's correct,
how do we get
through that sheet of ice?
Look for a crack.
Or make a crack.
Take something and smack it
into the ice until it buckles.
Wait a minute. What if we've
already made a crack in the ice?
When we first entered
the event horizon.
If we could find
our entry point,
we might be able to slip out
the way we came in.
We'd be looking for a subspace
instability in event horizon.
What would make it show
up on our sensors?
BOTH ( in unison ):
Warp particles.
If we saturate the event horizon
with warp particles,
we might be able to
see them escaping
through the rupture we
made when we entered.
Mr. Tuvok, take the main
deflector off-line.
Mr. Kim, reroute the port
and starboard plasma flow
to the main deflector.
We can use it to
generate a warp field.
Deflectors off-line.
Initializing plasma flow.
Release the warp particles.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Scanning the singularity.
Anything?
Not yet.
Warp particles
at full intensity.
I'm picking up something--
a slight irregularity.
It could be a rupture
in the event horizon.
Put it on screen.
It is a rupture, Captain.
It's 50 meters by...
ten meters.
Oh, it's too small.
It must have collapsed since
we first passed through it.
We found the crack. That's the
important thing.
Now, how do we
make it bigger?
Put a wedge in it
and force it open.
We could try
a dekyon beam.
All right,
Mr. Paris,
bring us closer.
Captain, if we get too close
to the rupture,
our warp engines
might make it collapse
even further.
Can we emit
a beam from here?
The rupture's over 50 million
kilometers away.
We don't have enough power to
project a dekyon beam that far.
We'll have to take
a shuttlecraft.
You'll need the best pilot
you've got in that
shuttle, Captain.
That'll be me.
Getting there is
the easy part, Mr. Paris.
We need someone who's familiar
with the finer points
of temporal mechanics,
and unless you've been
hiding your credentials,
I don't think that's you.
B'Elanna, you're with me.
The Bridge is yours,
Commander.
We've cleared Voyager.
Shields at
full strength.
We'll reach the rupture
in approximately
four and a half minutes.
Let's get that dekyon beam
on line.
Remodulating
emitters.
Captain... I want
to apologize
for losing my temper.
In your ready room.
I think maybe
you were hitting
a little bit too close
to home, you know?
I respect Chakotay,
but he's wrong.
I'm not officer material
and we both know it.
The truth is, I quit
the Academy because...
I realized I couldn't
make it in Starfleet.
And, believe me, no one
was sorry to see me go.
Professor Chapman was.
What?
He put a letter
in your permanent file
saying that, should you ever
reapply, he would support you.
He thought you were
one of the most
promising cadets
he'd ever taught.
I fought with him
almost every day.
I was always questioning his,
his methods, his assumptions,
and he was always slapping
me down like some upstart kid.
I was surprised he didn't
help me pack my bags.
Some professors like students
who challenge their assumptions,
B'Elanna.
And so do some captains.
Professor Chapman
wasn't alone.
Many of your teachers
thought you had the potential
to be an outstanding officer.
You had more friends at the
Academy than you realized.
We're 15 kilometers
from the rupture.
Start charging
the dekyon beam.
Dekyon beam on line.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Shields down to 62 percent.
Increase speed.
We have to get to that rupture
before these spatial distortions
tear us apart.
( suspenseful theme playing )
All right.
Let's open this hole in the ice
a little wider.
Initiate the dekyon beam.
( alarm beeping )
They've widened the rupture
by almost 35 percent.
PARIS:
They'll have to widen it
twice that much
before Voyager can
make it through.
Hold our position.
Mr. Tuvok, report.
The spatial distortions
are increasing.
KIM:
Hull integrity
has dropped
18 percent.
We've widened the opening
by over 65 percent.
I'd like another five
for safety.
We're losing power.
I don't think we're going
to get any more, Captain.
Let's get back to Voyager.
TUVOK:
The shuttle is returning,
Commander.
It appears as though
they've been damaged.
Their com system's down.
I am unable to raise them.
KIM:
The rupture's
now 120 meters
in diameter. That leaves us with
less
than two meters' clearance
on either side.
( dramatic theme playing )
Mr. Paris, as soon as we've
recovered the shuttlecraft,
lay in a course
toward the rupture
and take us out.
PARIS:
Aye, sir.
( dramatic theme swells )
Well, this is a problem.
JANEWAY:
One of them is
a temporal reflection
but which one?
I'm getting identical readings
from both ships.
TORRES:
Captain, the rupture
is starting to
collapse again.
If Voyager doesn't
get through it
within the next five minutes,
they'll never get out.
That means we have one chance
to pick the correct ship.
TORRES:
Simple choice--
port or starboard?
Starboard.
Port.
The port ship is more likely
to be the real one.
It's closer to the rupture.
That means-- That means
they're holding position
as close as they can
to the rupture,
waiting for us to dock
before they head out.
No. It may be closer
to the rupture,
but it's facing
the wrong direction.
The starboard ship is
facing away from us.
That means they're
trying to give us
easy access to the shuttlebay.
There has to be some way
to tell them apart
besides which direction
they're facing.
The starboard ship's thrusters
are at standby.
They're holding position
But the port ship is
moving toward the rupture.
Then I was right.
It's the port ship.
They're heading out.
Don't you see?
Voyager did move
toward the rupture
20 minutes ago when
we first discovered it.
That's why the port
ship is moving
toward it now.
It's a time-delayed reflection
of what we did before.
The starboard ship's
the real one.
They're waiting for us.
If you're wrong...
we're going to have
a long time to debate it.
( dramatic theme playing )
We're ready to dock.
All right.
Cut the thrusters.
Let's see what happens.
( sighs )
Feels like
a real ship to me.
Let's get back
to the Bridge.
Commander Chakotay, report.
We're almost to the rupture.
Mr. Paris is about to impress us
with his piloting skills.
The rupture's collapsing.
It's down to 110 meters wide.
That's too narrow.
We're not going to make it.
In command school, they taught
us to always remember
that maneuvering a starship
is a very delicate process,
but over the years,
I've learned that sometimes
you just have to punch
your way through.
Mr. Paris, full impulse power.
( dramatic theme playing )
Shields are down.
( crew chattering )
I'm losing power
to the port impulse engine.
Switching to auxiliary power.
Hull integrity failing.
Keep it together, Mr. Paris.
( majestic theme playing )
We've cleared
the event horizon, Captain.
We've returned
to normal space.
PARIS:
"Sometimes you just have
to punch your way through."
I'll have to remember that one.
JANEWAY:
Set a course.
I want to be at least
100 million kilometers
away from the singularity
before we begin repairs.
There they are-- your staff.
I'll try not to break
any of their noses.
First order of the day:
The Captain wants
the warp drive
back on line
by 1300 hours.
1300?
That's impossible.
Then maybe you need
to go break a few noses,
or at least... bend a few.
Lieutenant.
All right.
Get that isolinear bank
up and running,
and lock down
those plasma relays.
Please.
I'm going to be counting on you,
Lieutenant.
I'm not up-to-date on
the latest Starfleet protocols
and I know that you're
probably more familiar
with the quirks
of this warp engine
than I am right now.
I hope...
that I can depend on you.
I assure you, you'll never get
less than my best.
Lieutenant...
congratulations.
Welcome aboard.
( majestic theme playing )
Are you checking up
on your new Chief Engineer?
Observing.
And?
Two crew members
have already
filed complaints
about her promotion,
and she may be in for
a tough period of adjustment,
but I think B'Elanna's
going to make
a fine addition
to this crew.
Our crew.
Can I ask you a question...
off the record?
If things had happened
differently
and we were on the Maquis
ship now instead of Voyager,
would you have served under me?
One of the nice things
about being Captain
is that you can keep
some things to yourself.
DOCTOR ( over intercom ):
Sick Bay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
Is someone ever going
to come down here
and fix
my holographic projectors?
We're a little busy
right now, Doctor,
but I'll send a crew down
as soon as I can.
I would appreciate a certain
expediency in the matter.
Acknowledged.
Janeway out.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant
but whatever it is,
you're going to have
to take care of it yourself.
Oh, it's all right.
It's just a scratch, really.
You know...
I like you better this way.
( majestic theme playing )