Holding course 351 mark 10.
Warp 7.
We'll be passing a red dwarf
system in 40 minutes.
I can't tell yet if there
are any M-Class planets.
You ready?
No, I really want
to get on that transtator
assembly diagnostic.
Harry, I can't do this alone.
Sorry.
Oh, you're making a big mistake.
Can't you see
what's going to happen?
We're the only humans
out here, Harry.
People are going
to start pairing off
and if we don't get
to the Delaney sisters
in Stellar Cartography soon,
somebody else will.
I got a girl
back home.
So what?
I got five.
I plan on seeing mine again.
Harry, Harry, Harry,
Harry, Harry.
You really think
she's going to wait for you?
I hope so.
Let her go.
Let her have a husband
and kids and a good life,
while you and I have
the Delaney sisters.
I told you, I need to run
a transtator diagnostic.
You need to run
a self-diagnostic.
Look, they come as a pair.
It's a double date
or no date.
Come on.
I told them all about you.
What did you tell them
about me?
Uh, well, for one thing,
how you broke
the single-pilot speed record
at the Academy.
Record?
I never broke any record.
And who are they going
to check it with?
( console beeping )
( deep rumbling )
Report!
We're at the leading
edge of a shock wave.
Minor hull breach on Deck 3,
contained.
Shields are holding.
TORRES:
Engineering is undamaged,
Captain.
All systems operational.
Mr. Paris, can you identify
the source of the wave?
I'm not sure.
Scanners are picking
up a debris cloud
in the red dwarf system
we're approaching.
It consists of differentially
charged polaric ions,
Captain.
Differentially charged?
That would suggest
a massive detonation.
Are you familiar
with any intelligent life forms
in this system, Mr. Neelix?
Familiar?
Ah, not exactly,
uh, familiar.
Considerably less than
familiar, actually.
Adjust course to investigate.
Aye, Captain.
PARIS:
Entering the system, Captain.
Heading 010 mark 4.
NEELIX:
Kes...
what are you doing here?
I had to know.
Know? Know what?
The origin of the shock wave
is an M-Class planet, Captain.
We're within visual range.
On screen.
KIM:
All vegetation on the planet
has been destroyed.
No satellite system in orbit. No
evidence of spacecraft.
Life signs?
None.
PARIS: None.
But the polaric
radiation
may be interfering
with the scanners.
Take us into orbit.
Density patterns
on the surface
show artificial waterways
and a global
aqueduct system.
There is a civilization
down there, Captain.
Or there was.
What do we know
about surface conditions?
Radiation is within
acceptable levels.
Atmosphere:
breathable.
Mr. Paris, Tuvok,
you're with me.
Ms. Torres, meet us
in Transporter Room 2.
On my way.
Commander,
you have the Bridge.
TORRES:
The entire surface of the planet
was just... seared.
JANEWAY:
There was a chain reaction
in subspace,
very likely ignited
by the detonation
of one or more
polaric ion devices.
PARIS:
If that's what happened,
the people here
never had a chance.
TORRES:
They're gone... vaporized.
Everything organic
has basically been obliterated.
At least it
happened quickly.
Polaric detonation
would have swept through
this city in seconds.
TUVOK:
It recalls
the Chaltok IV incident.
TORRES:
Chaltok IV?
A Romulan research colony
was nearly destroyed
during a testing
of one of these devices.
It led to the Polaric
Test Ban Treaty of 2268.
So... we're looking
at the end of a war.
I wonder who won.
JANEWAY:
I'm not so sure
there was a war.
Look at these readings,
B'Elanna.
TORRES:
Polaric ion concentrations
are so high, I can't get
an accurate reading.
I'd say these conduits
were the source
of the explosion,
wouldn't you?
A civilization powered
by polaric ion energy?
That's what it looks like.
A time bomb
underneath every street,
running into every home.
NEELIX:
What do you mean,
you saw it?
How could
you see it?
I don't know.
What did you see?
( sobbing ):
I saw them...
burn...
their bodies...
ashes where they stood!
You felt the shock wave
in your sleep.
This is just
your imagination.
A strange coincidence.
I don't think so.
What else could it be?
It was...
it was almost
telepathic.
Telepathy is a message,
words, a voice...
What you're describing,
why, it's... almost like
the visions of Drakina
Forest dwellers.
Who?
A tribe with
paranormal abilities.
They can walk
into an empty room...
Neelix, my ancestors
were said to have
unusual mental abilities.
No one believes those stories.
I always have.
Look.
This may be some kind
of timepiece
stopped at the moment
of the explosion.
( children laughing )
What was that?
What?
Didn't you hear that?
Hear what,
Lieutenant?
Kids playing.
They were as close to me as...
( children, adults talking )
I don't understand.
I was here, in this square,
but there were people.
You never left here, Tom.
But I saw them.
Lots of people.
Children playing
and the sun was shining.
There was no evidence
of an explosion.
Everyone was alive and happy.
You were standing here
the whole time.
Your central nervous system
is showing a temporal flux,
but it's rapidly
returning to normal.
TUVOK:
The chain reaction has
shattered subspace, Captain.
I want everyone to stand
exactly where they are.
If Tuvok's right,
there may be subspace fractures
floating like icebergs
across the planet's surface.
Away team to Voyager.
Go ahead.
Four to beam up.
( children, adults talking )
Tuvok, B'Elanna?
( screaming )
Hey, calm down.
It's all right.
Now what's the problem?
I saw them!
They appeared
out of thin air!
They're some kind
of demons.
I saw them
with my own eyes.
I'm sorry we startled him.
We just came around the corner.
They're lying!
Shh, now.
Calm down.
You've been reading
too many of those Darkstorm
tales, young fellow.
There's no such thing
as demons.
But I'm telling you...
Ah, ah, ah,
run along now.
Have a confection bar
and calm down.
All right, everybody,
back to your business.
Nothing else to see here now.
Oh, sorry about that.
No problem.
Who knows what gets
into their heads, huh?
Oh, perhaps the
uniforms scared him.
We're not from
this area.
Come in on
the Continental Transport?
This morning.
Is, uh, that what
they're wearing
in Kalto province
these days?
Uh, this is, uh, a little
more formal than most.
You know how it is
when you travel.
We were actually looking
for a clothing shop.
We thought we'd change
into something more appropriate.
There's one
right over there.
I hope the rest of your stay
with us is more enjoyable.
I wish I could
say it will be.
MAN:
Need a timepiece?
Maybe you could help me.
I'm from... Kalto province.
I'm not used
to your timepieces.
They're no different
than Kalton timepieces.
Are you sure?
What do these numbers
stand for?
Rotations, intervals,
fractions.
Same as any timepiece.
14 kelodas.
A fair price.
I might stop back later.
If there's time.
If I understood correctly,
this world is going to be
destroyed sometime tomorrow.
CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's Log,
supplemental.
There's been no sign of Captain
Janeway or Lieutenant Paris
since they were lost
in a subspace fracture.
KIM:
This is one of the subspace
fractures we've located
with a magneton
scan of the surface.
This is the time
of the explosion
where the fracture opens.
The, as the shock waves
dissipate,
the fracture grows more narrow.
We believe that the Captain
and Lieutenant Paris
are trapped at the narrow end.
Shock waves from most
explosions dissipate
into the future, but we're
speculating-- Based in part
on what Paris
told us he saw--
That these dissipate
into the past.
That's consistent
with the subspace damage
we've observed.
Why haven't they
been able to return
as Mr. Paris did
the first time?
TORRES:
He wasn't all the way
inside a fracture.
Remember? We still saw Paris
standing there
even when he could
see the other side.
So it's possible the Captain
and Paris are existing
only hours and minutes
before the explosion occurs.
There's no way for us to measure
exactly how far back
these fractures go.
How do we find them?
If I know
Captain Janeway,
she would activate
a subspace beacon to assist us.
We're counting on it.
First, we have to find
a fracture
in a location where they've been
then we have to microscan
the fracture
to try to pick up the signal
from their subspace beacon.
Once we've identified
where and when they are,
then we have to widen
the fracture at that point.
How do you suggest we do that?
We're not sure yet.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
What?
Hmm?
Is something wrong?
Yes, terribly wrong.
Your brain is...
not on file.
Either your government
failed to transmit
the standard 15-501
Crew Personnel Report
or somebody at
Starfleet Medical
really fouled up.
I'm not a member
of the Starfleet crew.
We came aboard
at mid-expedition.
And no one asked you
for your medical histories
when you arrived?
Of course not--
That would be
the ship's
doctor's job.
My job.
If anyone had bothered
to tell me about new passengers,
but I seem to be
the last to know
just about everything
around here.
So. Tell me--
Just how many other
new arrivals are there?
Just us.
And the crew
from another ship
that was destroyed.
Another... crew?
That's nice.
This is the emergency
medical holographic system
to Captain Janeway.
She's not on board.
She's missing on the
surface of a planet.
Missing?
The Captain is missing?
It seems I've found myself
on the voyage of the damned.
Very well.
Please advise
the highest-ranking officer
who is not missing
to see me
at his earliest convenience.
You may shut off
my program now.
But you haven't told us anything
about her condition.
She's the healthiest member
of her species I've ever seen...
the only member of her species
I've ever seen.
You have a lovely brain.
It will make a fine
addition to our files.
I wouldn't worry.
If your species
has a history
of extraordinary
mental abilities,
this may simply be your way
of flexing those muscles
for the first time.
Living in space requires
the body to make
a variety of biological
adjustments.
This could be a side effect
of that process.
Go home.
Get a good night's sleep...
and drink plenty of fluids.
Fluids?
Everybody should drink
plenty of fluids.
Don't leave
without turning me off.
Computer, end program.
And call me in the morning.
We can assume that Voyager
will be looking for a way
to reach us.
I'll set my combadge
to emit a subspace beacon.
If they get close,
maybe they'll pick it up.
( sighs )
I know.
Maybe there's
some way...
Don't even think
about it, Tom.
The Prime Directive is clear.
We cannot allow our presence
to alter this planet's
natural course of events.
Even if the natural
course of events
is annihilation?
Yeah.
My father used to
talk at length to us
about the Prime Directive,
once a year-- Like
a holiday sermon.
He considered it
the guiding principle
of space exploration.
To be honest,
I tuned out most of
his sermons years ago.
Well, tune back into this one
because I agree with him.
You have no idea
what the consequences might be
once you involve yourself.
The consequences would have to
be better than mass destruction.
You're not to warn these people.
That's an order.
Oh, God. Come on.
I know you're lying.
Young man, we're here
on a business trip
and we have a lot
of work to do.
Officer told me you came here
on the Continental Transport.
That's right.
We're from Kalto province.
Yeah? Well, I just talked
to the transport attendant.
He told me four people
came today from Kalto.
Two of them were
a lot older than you
and they had a child with them.
Well, the attendant
was wrong.
That was us.
So where's the child?
We ate him.
Because we are demons
and we eat children.
And I haven't had
my supper yet.
( gasps in fright )
Sorry, I just figured
it was the quickest way.
Let's concentrate
on getting out of here.
The same subspace fractures
that brought us here
might still be around.
If they were caused
by a polaric explosion
is there any way we could use
polaric energy to get us back?
If we had access to
a polaric ion generator,
we could modify a tricorder
to emit a polaric field.
At the very least, it might
help us scan for a fracture.
I wonder where these
conduits get their power.
( angry yelling )
This is a lawful
demonstration.
We have a right
to be here!
Under normal
circumstances,
I'd say we should
come back tomorrow.
( gunfire )
( gunfire continues )
( groaning )
TORRES:
This device uses the
same polaric energy
that destroyed the planet.
At intense levels,
it can open a subspace fracture.
Wide enough for the Captain
and Paris to get through?
If we can
locate them,
this is capable
of bringing them back.
The logical place
to begin would be
at the same location
they disappeared.
The only problem is,
at the necessary intensity,
the polaric generator
will burn itself out
after 30 seconds at best.
Can't we reinitialize the
generator and try again?
Not at the same location.
Once we make an attempt
at any given location,
the damage to subspace
will make a second
attempt impossible.
How do we prevent one of us from
getting trapped in a fracture?
We've modified our tricorders
to detect the fractures
and all of us will be
wearing one of these.
It puts out an
anti-polaric field.
It should repel the fractures
when they get
within three meters.
Nice work.
NEELIX:
Ah, Commander.
Will you be going back
to the planet's surface?
We're getting ready
to leave right now.
I have to go with you.
There's nothing down there
you want to see, Kes.
That's what
I told her.
I've already seen it.
I have to go.
We're sorry
to involve you in this.
Pe'Nar Makull.
My colleague, Ny Terla.
Apparently, you just
happened to be
at the wrong place
at the wrong time.
I was just thinking
the very same thing.
What were you
doing there?
We're from Kalto province.
We were hoping to tour
your power facility...
compare it
to our own.
I've never seen a Kalton
with your color hair.
Well, now you have.
My friend thinks
you were sent
by the government
to infiltrate us.
Infiltrate?
You were there
when she got this.
Perhaps you were told
to put on a good show for us.
We don't even know why someone
would want to infiltrate you.
( laughs )
That's hard to believe.
Even in Kalto, there are
protests against polaric energy.
We're not spies.
When was the last time
you were in a power plant?
Not since we left home.
You weren't
in that plant yesterday?
We were just getting there
when we stumbled into you.
We know you're not
telling the truth.
We have safety monitors
to measure polaric energy.
When you were brought here,
they registered five times
the normal readings.
To register levels this high,
you were either inside
that plant yesterday
or...
at the site
of a polaric disaster
worse than any in the history
of this planet.
What is it?
It's as though I can sense
the people who were here.
I know.
It's like walking
through a graveyard.
No.
It's more than that.
I almost feel...
as if I could touch
the people who were here.
What have you found?
TUVOK:
The scanners are not showing
any subspace fractures
in the area now.
That probably indicates
the subspace damage
is beginning to dissipate.
If that's true,
it's going to be harder
to locate Tom and the Captain.
Commander, I'm picking up
a signal from a combadge.
The subspace beacon?
No, it's not on subspace.
It's here... now.
Kim to Janeway.
Kim to Paris.
Can we locate
the source of the signal?
Yes, sir.
This way.
What's your name?
Janeway.
Unusual name.
Not where I'm from.
What part of Kalto province
was that again?
I don't see any point in this.
There is a point,
a very important one.
It has to do
with our schedule
and whether we
can keep it or not.
Can we?
I don't know.
Do they know our plan?
I have no idea.
Let me go!
Look what I caught
sneaking around
outside.
I'm still not showing
any life signs.
The boy has nothing
to do with any of this.
Is he yours?
No. He's just somebody
we met here.
Don't trust them.
They aren't
who they say they are.
Really?
Thanks, kid.
Look, this is all
a misunderstanding.
They lied about coming here
on the
Continental Transport.
I talked to
the attendant myself.
Let me go...
What do we do with him?
We can't let him go.
Just put him over there
with the other.
Now stay quiet.
The combadge is designed
to self-activate
when the casing is destroyed...
to help searchers
locate victims.
I guess it means they were
caught in the explosion.
It only means
their combadges
were caught in
the explosion.
Further speculation
serves no purpose.
I suggest we search for
other tangible evidence.
None of us have seen devices
like these before.
Terla believes
they're spy equipment.
They're for surveying property.
I've been thinking
of buying land here.
I need to survey it.
I'd be curious
to know how they work.
Would you show me?
But then one of them
might be a weapon.
And I wouldn't want
you to show me
how that works, would I?
Hey, kid.
You were right
about one thing.
I was lying.
I don't eat children.
You don't scare me.
My father works
for the Media Bureau.
And when I tell him
all about this, he'll...
What is he,
some kind of journalist?
Yes, and so am I.
Is that right?
I report for my school journal.
That's right where everyone's
going to find out about you
when I write about this
in next week's edition.
What's your name?
Latika.
I'm sorry.
For what?
I just am.
MAKULL:
I realize how this
must appear to you,
but I'm just a patriot.
A patriot?
I sincerely believe
polaric energy
has the potential
to destroy this entire world.
And I take it, very few people
here agree with you?
We have more support
since the accident at Markov.
We know the companies
are afraid of us.
We know they've increased
security at all their plants,
but it will not be
enough to stop us.
We can't wait another week.
We have to move up
the schedule.
We know they're
not telling us the truth.
We have to assume
the government sent them.
Tell everyone we begin
at 0400 tomorrow.
Wait a minute.
Captain...?
Kes...
Do you have something
to tell me, Janeway--
If that's
your real name?
It is my real name.
Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
I can feel their presence.
Please elaborate.
How can you feel
their presence?
I don't know.
I just can.
They've been in this room.
I know it.
Is there a subspace fracture
anywhere in here?
Affirmative.
Set up the equipment.
You wanted the truth.
All right.
Here's the truth.
We're from the future--
Exactly one day in the future.
You mean I was right?
We weren't allowed to tell.
At least, I thought we weren't.
In a few hours from now,
there will be a serious accident
on this world.
It will be caused
by a polaric detonation.
We came here
in an interstellar ship
to investigate
that explosion.
When we arrived,
we were exposed
to the polaric radiation.
Showing a subspace fracture.
Coordinates: 141 by 21 by 14.
Five percent drift.
Range: four meters.
Got it.
Initiating generator.
Initiating microscan
of the subspace fracture.
It's very likely that whatever
you're planning to do
could be responsible
for this tragedy.
And somehow, you were able
to come back here to warn us?
The explosion had an aftereffect
that no one expected.
It created fractures
in time.
We fell through
one of those
fractures.
Interstellar ships,
fractures in time--
Do you honestly expect
us to believe all this?
I found them.
Scanners are picking up
a subspace beacon.
Adjusting penetration
coordinates to match.
I'll try to open up
the other end.
Chakotay to Janeway.
Captain, can you read us?
Eavesdropping devices.
No.
But they are for communication.
My crew is trying
to contact me.
From the future,
of course.
Get the particle injector.
Bring them with us.
The boy too.
I have an idea
how they can help.
Chakotay to Janeway.
Can you read me?
Please respond.
PARIS:
I don't get it, Captain.
This morning
you were giving orders
about not interfering
because of the Prime Directive.
Now you're telling them
everything.
I told them the truth
when I realized
we'd already violated
the Prime Directive
in the worst
possible manner.
How did we do that?
Just by being here.
Because if we hadn't been here,
it's very possible this world
would not have been destroyed.
What?
Think about it, Tom.
Before we got involved,
these people were planning
to commit some kind
of sabotage next week.
We were the ones who forced
a change in their schedule.
Because of us, they decided
to begin today at 400 rotations
and we know the detonation
takes place today
just after 401.
401:22:84.
Wait a minute.
You're saying we're
responsible for an explosion
even though it occurred
before our ship arrived here?
We've traveled back
to a point in time
before the explosion.
So, yes, we can be
responsible for it.
Let's say we never came
and their plans
didn't change.
Wouldn't the accident simply
have occurred next week
instead of today?
Who knows what might have
happened between now and then.
They could have
been arrested
before they got a chance
to carry it out.
Conditions at the plant
might not have been
the same next week.
But it's become
our problem now, Tom,
and we have got to find
a way to solve it.
We're running out of time.
The subspace fractures
are closing.
We've lost over 70 percent
of them.
At this point, we're suggesting
we concentrate our search
at the flash point.
May I ask
what you expect
to accomplish by doing that?
We figure the Captain and Paris
might have looked
for the origin of the explosion
to try and prevent it.
Unlikely.
It would be a highly
questionable decision
in light of the Prime Directive.
If it were me, I would
have tried to get there.
The issue is whether
Captain Janeway would go there,
not you, Commander.
You think you can
locate the flash point?
We already have.
Let's go.
Your job is to get us
past the guards.
We'll tell them
you're bringing us here
to negotiate a settlement
of our dispute
with the power company.
I cannot and will not
do anything to help you.
Think before
you say no.
Terla has a weapon
trained on the boy.
If shooting begins,
he'll be the first victim.
Is there something
I can do for you?
She's a government
representative
on official business.
I am a hostage.
These men are here
to break into the plant.
Their lives are
on your conscience, Janeway!
You saved my life.
Don't waste...
time with me, Captain.
Got to stop them.
Will you stay with him
until help arrives?
Sure he will.
The kid and I...
( groaning )
we're old friends now,
aren't we?
Yeah.
I'll be back for you.
We'll be here.
( murmuring voices )
The polaric levels
are higher here
than any place
we've been so far.
This was undoubtedly
the flash point
of the explosion.
Whatever went wrong,
it started here.
Do we have subspace fractures
to work with in here?
Affirmative.
They remain quite numerous
in this area.
Set up the equipment.
KIM:
Aye, sir.
I need the injector.
Just hand that bag
to me.
TUVOK:
41 by 310.
Two percent drift.
Range: 6 meters.
Mark.
I have it.
Initiating generator.
Scanning
for the subspace beacon.
It doesn't look like
they were here.
It is highly unlikely
that Captain Janeway
would come here to...
No, the Captain did come.
She was here.
This is where she died.
Everybody on this planet
has less than
three minutes to live
if you go through
with this, Makull.
Don't!
What exactly do you think
we are planning to do here?
I assume you're going
to sabotage the plant
probably by detonating
some kind of device.
We're not stupid enough
to blow up anything here.
That may be true,
but something will go wrong.
Nothing is going to go wrong
unless you fire that weapon
near a polaric conduit.
For everyone's safety,
I suggest you put it down.
Give me the bag.
All right, then... we'll wait.
If Kes is right,
the Captain was here
at the moment
the explosion occurred.
Is there any way
to break through subspace
a few minutes
before the detonation?
If the widest point
of the fracture
represents the time
of the explosion,
couldn't we open a hole
just before
the widest point?
There's no way we could pinpoint
the exact time
we'd be penetrating, but we
could make an educated guess.
TUVOK
I feel it is
my duty to point out
there is absolutely
no logical reason
to believe Kes is correct.
However,
since I have no alternative
course of action
to recommend at this time,
I suggest we proceed.
TORRES:
Commander?
What time is it?
401 rotations plus 21.
We'll just wait until... 23.
Twenty-three?
What's the importance of 23?
Oh.
This is all about
the alleged time
of our self-annihilation.
All right.
Let's just see
if we can all get through the...
What's going on?
They're cutting
through subspace.
My God.
It's going to intersect
with the conduit wall.
Our own rescue attempt.
That's what sets it off.
My weapon may be able
to seal that hole.
It's our only chance.
I'm getting nadion particle
resistance from the other side.
Increasing generator
to maximum output.
The generator's overloading.
I don't understand.
It's not working.
We're not penetrating
the fracture.
Harry, Harry, Harry,
Harry, Harry.
You really think
she's going to wait for you?
I hope so.
Let her go.
Let her have a husband
and kids and a good life,
while you and I have
the Delaney sisters.
I told you I need to run
a transtator diagnostic.
You need to run
a self-diagnostic.
Look, they come as a pair.
It's a double date
or no date.
Come on.
I told them all about you.
What did you tell them
about me?
Uh, well, for one thing,
how you broke
the single-pilot speed record
at the Academy.
Record?
I never broke any record.
And who are they going
to check it with?
Chakotay to Captain Janeway.
Yes, Commander.
We've identified
an M-Class planet
in the red dwarf system
we're approaching.
Do you want to change
course to investigate?
Are you familiar with
any intelligent life-forms
in this system, Mr. Neelix?
Familiar?
Ah, not exactly familiar.
Considerably less
than familiar, actually.
Kes...
what are you doing here?
I had to know.
Know?
Know what?
The planet...
everyone was killed.
There was this terrible
explosion.
You, you had a bad dream.
No. It was more
than a dream.
Mr. Tuvok, any
indications of trouble
on that M-Class
planet?
Negative, Captain.
Is it populated?
Sensors do show humanoid life.
There is
no satellite system
and no indications
of spacecraft
in the vicinity.
It appears to be
a pre-warp civilization.
Which means as a policy,
we don't involve ourselves
in their affairs.
Of course.
A most enlightened
philosophy.
Come on, Kes.
I'm sorry.
Captain...
Is it possible
to see this planet
on the viewscreen?
JANEWAY:
There it is.
Thank you.
Come on.
Just...
JANEWAY:
Enter the planet's
coordinates into the log
and maintain present heading,
Commander.
Warp 6.
CHAKOTAY:
Aye, Captain.