CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE
48532.4.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY
TO A ROGUE PLANETOID
WHICH MR. NEELIX TELLS US
IS AN EXTREMELY RICH SOURCE
OF RAW DILITHIUM.
IF HE'S RIGHT,
THIS COULD GO A LONG WAY
TOWARD EASING
OUR POWER SHORTAGE.
ASSUMING WE DO FIND DILITHIUM
ON THIS PLANETOID
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
A REFINING FACILITY
ON THE SHIP
TO PROCESS IT.
LIEUTENANT TORRES
HAS ALREADY ASKED PERMISSION
TO START MODIFICATIONS
TO THE AUXILIARY
IMPULSE REACTOR.
IT COULD BE CONVERTED INTO
A CRUDE DILITHIUM REFINERY.
THE IMPULSE REACTOR?
SOMETIMES I THINK B'ELANNA
GOES OUT OF HER WAY
TO FIND SOLUTIONS THAT IGNORE
STARFLEET PROCEDURES.
HER ARGUMENTS ARE
QUITE CONVINCING.
SHE THINKS
IT CAN BE DONE SAFELY.
I'M SURE IT CAN.
TELL HER I WANT
REGULAR REPORTS
ON HER PROGRESS
EVERY STEP OF THE WAY.
ARE YOU SURE YOU WON'T
JOIN ME FOR BREAKFAST?
I WAS THINKING
OF HAVING EGGS BENEDICT
WITH ASPARAGUS,
STRAWBERRIES AND CREAM...
I SAID I WAS
THINKING ABOUT IT.
I'M ACTUALLY HAVING
RATION PACK NUMBER FIVE--
STEWED TOMATOES
WITH DEHYDRATED EGGS.
MMM, SOUNDS DELICIOUS
BUT I'VE ALREADY HAD
MY VACUUM-PACKED OATMEAL
THIS MORNING.
I'LL SEE YOU ON THE BRIDGE.
HERE YOU ARE.
HOPE YOU ENJOY IT.
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
CAPTAIN, YOU CAUGHT ME
BY SURPRISE.
I COULD SAY THE SAME THING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I KNOW HOW YOU AND THE
OTHER... SENIOR OFFICERS
HAVE BEEN, EXCUSE ME,
DISAPPOINTED WITH THE RATIONS
LATELY
SO I THOUGHT I'D USE
A FEW OF THE VEGETABLES
FROM THE HYDROPONICS BAY
AND WHIP UP A LITTLE BREAKFAST.
YOU HAVE TURNED THIS
INTO A GALLEY?
IT WASN'T EASY.
I HAD TO COMPLETELY RE-ROUTE
THE MESS HALL POWER CONDUITS
AND SCROUNGE A LOT OF SUPPLIES
FROM ALL OVER THE SHIP
BUT THAT'S MY SPECIALTY--
MAKING SOMETHING OUT OF NOTHING.
I KNOW IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
MUCH NOW, BUT IN A FEW DAYS
YOU'LL SWEAR THERE'D BEEN
A GALLEY HERE FOR YEARS.
CAREFUL, THAT ONE IS
A LITTLE SPICY.
NEELIX...
WHO APPROVED THIS?
UH, WELL... NO ONE.
WELL, YOU MIGHT HAVE
ASKED ME FIRST.
THIS USED TO BE
MY PRIVATE DINING ROOM.
YOUR DINING ROOM?
IF YOU HAD CHECKED THE SHIP'S
DIRECTORY, YOU'D HAVE NOTICED
THAT CABIN 125-ALPHA, DECK TWO
IS DESIGNATED AS THE CAPTAIN'S
PRIVATE DINING ROOM.
OH... THEN I GUESS THAT
YOU'LL BE WANTING ME
TO MOVE ALL OF THIS STUFF
OUT OF YOUR WAY?
Chakotay:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
GO AHEAD.
We're approaching
the rogue planetoid, Captain.
ON MY WAY.
I WANT YOU TO COME WITH ME.
WE WILL DEAL
WITH THIS LATER.
ENSIGN PARSONS, WOULD YOU MIND
KEEPING AN EYE ON THINGS
UNTIL I GET BACK...
AND ROTATE THE DARVOT FRITTERS
EVERY TEN MINUTES
UNTIL THEY TURN
A DEEP CHARTREUSE.
AND REMEMBER--
ONE TO A CUSTOMER.
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND?
WE'RE PICKING UP DEFINITE
DILITHIUM SIGNATURES, CAPTAIN.
THE STRONGEST READINGS
ARE ORIGINATING FROM TEN
TO 20 KILOMETERS
INSIDE THE PLANETOID.
IT ALSO LOOKS LIKE THERE'S A
SERIES OF SUBTERRANEAN CAVES
WITH AN OXYGEN-NITROGEN
ATMOSPHERE.
CLASS M. IT WILL MAKE MINING
A LOT EASIER
IF WE CAN GO IN
WITHOUT ENVIRONMENTAL SUITS.
HOW MUCH DILITHIUM
ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
IT'S HARD
TO GET A PRECISE READING.
IT COULD BE ANYWHERE FROM 500
TO 1,000 METRIC TONS.
JUST AS I SAID.
I BET THERE'S A FEW
YALLITIAN ENGINEERS
WHO'D GIVE ALL THREE
OF THEIR SPINAL COLUMNS
TO KNOW WHERE THIS PLANET IS.
COMMANDER, TAKE AN AWAY TEAM
DOWN INTO THOSE CAVES AND DO
A PRELIMINARY GEOLOGICAL
ANALYSIS.
LIEUTENANT, YOU'D BETTER GET
YOUR DILITHIUM REFINERY ON-LINE.
IT'LL BE READY TO GO
IN THREE DAYS.
ENSIGN KIM.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WITH YOU.
I'VE BEEN STUDYING
MY TRICORDER
OPERATIONS MANUAL.
LIEUTENANT TORRES HAS
BROUGHT ME UP-TO-DATE
ON DILITHIUM GEOPHYSICS.
I'VE BEEN PREPARING
FOR THIS MISSION ALL WEEK.
VERY WELL, MR. NEELIX.
I THINK YOU'LL FIND ME
EXTREMELY HELPFUL, COMMANDER.
I REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
THAT I FLEW PAST THIS PLANET.
IT WAS ABOUT
THREE YEARS AGO...
Kim:
DECK FOUR.
LOOKS LIKE THERE ARE SEVERAL
LARGE DEPOSITS
IN THIS GENERAL VICINITY.
LET'S SPLIT UP AND BEGIN TAKING
GEOLOGICAL SCANS.
KEEP YOUR COM CHANNELS
OPEN AT ALL TIMES
AND DON'T WANDER TOO FAR.
STAY WITHIN
A 50-METER RADIUS
OF THIS POSITION.
CHAKOTAY TO KIM.
Go ahead.
I'M STILL PICKING UP
DILITHIUM SIGNATURES,
BUT THERE ARE NO
DILITHIUM FORMATIONS HERE.
HAVE YOU FOUND ANYTHING YET?
I'M RUNNING A GEO-STRATAL
ANALYSIS OF THE ROCK
IN THIS VICINITY.
BUT SO FAR, THERE'S NO
INDICATION OF ANY DILITHIUM.
Keep looking.
NEELIX TO COMMANDER CHAKOTAY.
Go ahead.
I THINK I FOUND SOMETHING.
A LARGE CAVERN APPROXIMATELY
20 METERS FROM MY POSITION.
I'M READING A HUGE
DILITHIUM FORMATION THERE.
Don't go any further, Neelix.
STAY WITHIN THE SEARCH RADIUS.
I'LL BE WITH YOU IN A MINUTE.
BUT IT'S RIGHT HERE!
I'M IN THE CAVERN NOW,
COMMANDER, BUT...
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THIS.
Let me guess. Nothing there?
NOT SO MUCH AS A SLIVER
OF DILITHIUM.
AND YET
ACCORDING TO MY READINGS
I SHOULD BE SURROUNDED BY IT.
ALL RIGHT, I'VE HAD ENOUGH
OF THIS.
KIM, NEELIX, WE'RE HEADING
BACK TO THE SHIP.
Rendezvous with the...
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'M GETTING UNUSUAL READINGS
FROM THIS ROCK FACE.
TRACES OF ORGANIC ENERGY.
LOOKS LIKE
A BIO-ELECTRICAL SIGNATURE.
I THINK THERE'S SOMETHING ALIVE
DOWN HERE.
IT'S ABOUT TWO METERS
INTO THIS ROCK FACE.
Chakotay:
Neelix, I said get back here.
Neelix, did you hear
what I said?
JUST ONE MINUTE, COMMANDER.
HELLO?
IS THERE SOMEONE THERE?
I KNOW THERE'S SOMEBODY...
( screaming )
NEELIX, WHAT'S WRONG?
NEELIX!
KIM!
I'M ON MY WAY, SIR.
I CAN'T BE SURE, BUT I THINK
HE'S GOING INTO SHOCK.
CHAKOTAY TO VOYAGER--
MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
BEAM US DIRECTLY
TO SICK BAY.
GET THE BLOOD-GAS INFUSER.
THE WHAT?
EQUIPMENT STORAGE UNIT TWO--
SECOND SHELF ON THE LEFT, NOW.
HOLD HIM STILL.
WHAT'S HAPPENING, DOCTOR?
HE'S GOING INTO A COMA.
THE INFUSER WILL KEEP
HIS OXYGEN LEVEL STABLE
FOR THE NEXT HOUR OR SO,
BUT AFTER THAT HE'LL DIE.
HIS LUNGS HAVE BEEN REMOVED.
BY THE TIME WE GOT TO HIM,
HE WAS UNCONSCIOUS.
HOW COULD ANYONE REMOVE
HIS ORGANS SO QUICKLY?
THE DOCTOR SAYS
WHOEVER DID THIS
USED SOME KIND OF TRANSPORTER
TO BEAM THE LUNGS
DIRECTLY OUT OF HIS BODY.
WHAT HAPPENED?
IT APPEARS THAT NEELIX
WAS ATTACKED.
WE DON'T KNOW
HOW IT HAPPENED
BUT SOMEONE HAS SURGICALLY
REMOVED HIS LUNGS.
DID YOU FIND ANY EVIDENCE
OF THE LIFE SIGN
THAT NEELIX REPORTED?
NO.
CAPTAIN, I'VE ANALYZED THE
SENSOR LOGS FROM NEELIX'S
TRICORDER.
THE BIO-SCANNER PICKED UP
A SINGLE CLASS-THREE
HUMANOID ORGANISM.
THE BLOOD-GAS INFUSER
WILL KEEP HIM ALIVE
FOR ANOTHER 47 MINUTES.
THE ONLY CHANCE FOR HIS SURVIVAL
I SEE AT THE MOMENT
IS TO GET HIS OWN LUNGS BACK.
CAN'T WE FIT HIM WITH A PAIR OF
ARTIFICIAL LUNGS?
HIS RESPIRATORY SYSTEM
IS DIRECTLY LINKED
TO MULTIPLE POINTS
ALONG HIS SPINAL COLUMN.
IT'S TOO COMPLEX
TO REPLICATE.
I MAY BE ABLE TO SURGICALLY
REATTACH THE ORGANS
IF WE GET THEM BACK.
IN THE MEANTIME, I'LL HAVE
TO SEARCH FOR OTHER OPTIONS.
COMMANDER, I'M TAKING
AN AWAY TEAM BACK TO THE PLANET.
YOU'RE IN CHARGE
UNTIL WE RETURN.
INFORM MR. TUVOK
I WANT THREE
ARMED SECURITY
DETACHMENTS TO ACCOMPANY US.
ISSUE TYPE-THREE PHASERS.
MR. PARIS,
DID THEY TEACH YOU HOW TO RUN
A RESPIRATORY SERIES
IN YOUR BIOCHEMISTRY CLASSES
AT THE ACADEMY?
NO, I'M AFRAID THEY DIDN'T.
FINE. I'LL RUN IT MYSELF.
GET ME A PULMONARY SCANNER.
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO ASK
YOU TO LEAVE.
I'M NOT LEAVING.
ALL RIGHT. JUST KEEP
OUT OF THE WAY.
HERE IT IS. THIS IS WHERE
NEELIX WAS STANDING
WHEN HE WAS ATTACKED.
ACCORDING TO
HIS TRICORDER LOG
HE WAS SCANNING
THIS ROCK FACE
WHEN HE DETECTED
THE LIFE SIGN.
NEELIX SAID THERE
WAS A LIFE SIGN
TWO METERS BEHIND THIS WALL.
BUT MY TRICORDER SAYS
THERE'S NOTHING BUT SOLID ROCK
FOR ANOTHER 15 METERS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE OUR TRICORDERS
AREN'T GIVING THE REAL PICTURE
BEHIND WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
WAIT A MINUTE.
THE ROCK IS WARMER HERE.
YOU'RE RIGHT, CAPTAIN.
A TWO-DEGREE DIFFERENTIAL
IN THIS SECTION OF THE WALL.
THERE ARE NO NATURAL
GEOLOGICAL PHENOMENA
THAT COULD BE CREATING
THIS HEAT SOURCE.
LET'S MAKE A LITTLE HEAT
OF OUR OWN.
Tuvok:
THERE WAS A HIGHLY SOPHISTICATED
FORCE FIELD IN PLACE.
THERE'S A CHAMBER DOWN
THIS CORRIDOR.
DOC, I THINK HIS CELLULAR
TOXICITY LEVEL IS RISING.
IT'S UP TO 32 PERCENT.
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
STABILIZE THOSE LEVELS.
GET ME A CYTOPLASMIC
STIMULATOR.
WE DON'T HAVE ONE.
THEN REPLICATE ONE.
YEAH.
THE DESIGN SCHEMATICS ARE IN
THE SHIP'S MEDICAL DATABASE.
RIGHT.
THE MAN DRIVES
A 700,000-TON STARSHIP
SO SOMEBODY THINKS
HE'D MAKE A GOOD MEDIC.
I CAN SURVIVE WITH ONE
LUNG, CAN'T I?
WHAT IF I DONATED
A LUNG TO NEELIX?
A TRANSPLANT
IS NOT AN OPTION.
NO ONE ABOARD IS A COMPATIBLE
MATCH FOR A TALAXIAN.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED
A COMPLETELY NEW WAY
TO OXYGENATE
HIS BLOOD SUPPLY
AND RELAY NEURO-ELECTRICAL
IMPULSES.
OUR REPLICATORS
CAN'T REPRODUCE
COMPATIBLE ARTIFICIAL
ORGANS FOR HIM
BUT MAYBE THERE'S A WAY
TO MIMIC THEIR FUNCTIONS
AND GIVE US DIRECT CONTROL
OF HIS RESPIRATORY SYSTEM.
COMPUTER, IS THERE AN
IDENTIFICATION MATRIX
ON MR. NEELIX FROM THE LAST TIME
HE USED THE TRANSPORTER?
Affirmative.
TRANSFER IT TO CONSOLE FOUR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IM USING THE TRANSPORTER MATRIX
TO GET EXACT SPECIFICATIONS
FOR NEELIX'S LUNGS.
I THOUGHT YOU JUST SAID
WE CAN'T REPLICATE HIS LUNGS.
WE CAN'T, BUT IF I CAN
RECONFIGURE MY EMITTER ARRAY
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO CREATE
A PAIR OF HOLOGRAPHIC LUNGS
FOR MR. NEELIX.
HOLOGRAPHIC LUNGS?
IF IT'S SUCCESSFUL,
WE CAN PRECISELY CONTROL
HIS PULMONARY FUNCTIONS
TO ALLOW NORMAL BREATHING.
BUT A HOLOGRAM IS JUST
A PROJECTION OF LIGHT
HELD IN A MAGNETIC
CONTAINMENT FIELD.
THERE'S NO REAL MATTER
INVOLVED.
NOW...
YOU HIT ME.
THE MAGNETIC
CONTAINMENT FIELD
THAT CREATES THE ILLUSION
OF MY BODY
CAN BE MODULATED TO ALLOW
MATTER TO PASS THROUGH IT
OR... BE STOPPED.
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO MODULATE
THE HOLOGRAPHIC LUNGS
IN THE SAME WAY,
ALLOWING OXYGEN
AND CARBON DIOXIDE
TO PASS FROM THE LUNGS
THE BLOODSTREAM.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THIS MEANS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO TO HIM?
THERE'S NO TIME TO EXPLAIN
THE EXACT PROCEDURE
TO YOU RIGHT NOW.
OH, WELL, MAKE THE TIME
BECAUSE I'M NOT GOING
TO LET YOU
PERFORM ANY EXPERIMENTAL
SURGERY ON NEELIX
UNTIL I KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'RE DOING
AND WHAT THE RISKS ARE.
THE RISK IS
THAT IT WON'T WORK.
AND IF IT DOESN'T,
HE'LL DIE.
BUT IT IS HIS ONLY
IMMEDIATE CHANCE FOR SURVIVAL.
IF HE DOES SURVIVE
HE'LL HAVE TO BE HELD MOTIONLESS
IN AN ISOTROPIC RESTRAINT.
THE LUNGS NEED TO BE
PERFECTLY ALIGNED
TO HIS INTERNAL PHYSIOLOGY.
THE COMPUTER WON'T BE ABLE
TO COMPENSATE
FOR ANY BODY MOVEMENT
WHATSOEVER.
HOW LONG WILL HE
HAVE TO STAY LIKE THAT?
FOR THE REST OF HIS LIFE
UNLESS THE HOLO-LUNGS CAN BE
REPLACED BY HIS ORIGINAL ORGANS.
AND HE WILL NEVER
BE ABLE TO LEAVE
THE HOLOGRAPHIC ENVIRONMENT
OF THIS ROOM.
THE HOLO-LUNGS WOULD DISAPPEAR
THE MOMENT HE WENT OUT THE DOOR.
KES, I KNOW IT SOUNDS
PRETTY GRIM
BUT IT'S BETTER THAN
LOSING HIM COMPLETELY.
THIS WAY, HE'LL STILL
BE ALIVE.
AND MAYBE WE CAN FIND
A BETTER SOLUTION
SOMEWHERE DOWN THE ROAD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
NEELIX WOULD WANT?
I'M NOT SURE, BUT I DO KNOW
THAT I WANT HIM TO LIVE.
THIS ROOM IS THE SOURCE
OF THE DILITHIUM SIGNATURE
WE DETECTED EARLIER.
THE POWER SYSTEMS HERE
ARE RUNNING ON AN UNUSUAL
DILITHIUM MATRIX.
SO THERE ARE ACTUALLY
NO DILITHIUM DEPOSITS
ON THIS PLANET?
IT WOULD APPEAR NOT.
ARE THESE... ORGANS?
THIS LOOKS LIKE SOME KIND
OF STORAGE FACILITY.
I WOULD SAY YOU ARE CORRECT,
CAPTAIN.
THIS APPEARS TO BE
A BIOLOGICAL REPOSITORY.
ANY SIGN OF NEELIX'S LUNGS?
NEGATIVE.
THERE IS, HOWEVER,
A KAZON LIVER.
AND ALTHOUGH I CANNOT IDENTIFY
THE OTHER ORGANS ON DISPLAY HERE
I WOULD SAY THEY BEAR
A STRIKING SIMILARITY
TO PULMONARY ORGANS,
EPIDERMAL TISSUE
OCULAR NERVE FIBER...
SAVE THE CATALOGING
FOR LATER, TUVOK.
ACCORDING TO MY TRICORDER,
THERE WAS A LIFE FORM
IN THIS ROOM
LESS THAN TEN MINUTES AGO.
CAPTAIN.
OPEN IT.
ONE LIFE SIGN
20 METERS AHEAD.
LET'S GO.
( gagging )
THEY'VE ERECTED A FORCE FIELD
WITH A ROTATING PHASE
MODULATION.
WE WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
DISRUPT IT.
Chakotay:
Voyager to Captain Janeway.
GO AHEAD.
We've just picked up
AN ALIEN SHIP
LEAVING THE PLANET.
TRACTOR THEM, COMMANDER.
Sorry, Captain.
They went into warp too quickly.
BEAM US BACK.
AS SOON AS WE'RE ABOARD,
LAY IN A COURSE
for pursuit, maximum warp.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
OKAY...
THE ISOTROPIC RESTRAINT
IS ACTIVATED
HE WON'T BE ABLE TO MOVE
MORE THAN TWO MICRONS
IN ANY DIRECTION.
ONE MICRON
WOULD BE PREFERABLE
BUT I SUPPOSE
IT'LL HAVE TO DO.
INITIATING THE
HOLOGRAPHIC EMITTER ARRAY
HIS CELLULAR TOXICITY IS RISING.
82 PERCENT.
86 PERCENT.
COMPUTER, ACTIVATE PROGRAM
NEELIX ONE.
DEACTIVATE THE INFUSER.
IT'S OFFLINE.
HERE WE GO.
90 PERCENT.
95 PERCENT.
( raspy breathing )
TOXICITY RETURNING
TO NORMAL.
CAPTAIN'S LOG SUPPLEMENTAL:
WE ARE PURSUING THE ALIEN SHIP
FROM THE MOON.
THEY ARE NOT RESPONDING
TO HAILS.
AND IT APPEARS THAT OUR TWO
SHIPS ARE EVENLY MATCHED
FOR SPEED.
HOLOGRAPHIC LUNGS?
YES.
AND THEY'RE WORKING PERFECTLY,
IF I DO SAY SO MYSELF.
( gasping )
TRY TO BREATHE NORMALLY.
HOW LONG CAN I LIVE LIKE THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
THIS IS AN UNPRECEDENTED
MEDICAL PROCEDURE.
WE WILL BE CLOSELY MONITORING
YOUR CONDITION.
WHEN DO I GET OUT
OF THIS RESTRAINT?
UNLESS CAPTAIN JANEWAY
IS SUCCESSFUL IN RETRIEVING
YOUR ORIGINAL LUNGS
YOU'LL HAVE TO STAY
IN THE ISOTROPIC RESTRAINT
INDEFINITELY.
INDEFINITELY?
YOU MEAN I...
I COULD BE IN HERE
THE REST OF MY LIFE?
YES.
BUT WE'RE TRYING
TO FIND THE ALIENS
THAT DID THIS TO YOU.
THE CAPTAIN IS DOING
EVERYTHING SHE CAN.
WELL...
IF I'M GOING TO BE
IN HERE A WHILE
NOW'S AS GOOD A TIME
AS ANY TO TELL YOU
YOUR CEILING IS HIDEOUS.
I DIDN'T DESIGN THE ROOM.
I JUST WORK HERE.
SOMETHING WITH A BIT OF COLOR
WOULD HELP.
MAYBE A NICE TAPESTRY
OR A PAINTING.
UH, COULD YOU DIM THE LIGHTS
A LITTLE?
I'M A DOCTOR, MR. NEELIX,
NOT A DECORATOR.
PERHAPS YOU WOULD BE WILLING
TO ACCOMMODATE
HIS AESTHETIC NEEDS.
AND SOME MUSIC
WOULD BE NICE.
OR BETTER YET,
ARE YOU PROGRAMMED
TO SING?
Janeway to Paris.
Please report to the bridge.
I'M ON MY WAY, CAPTAIN.
YOU KNOW WHERE I AM
IF YOU NEED ME.
THANKS FOR EVERYTHING.
OH, FINE.
I HAVE A LITTLE ACCIDENT
I LOSE A PAIR OF LUNGS,
AND THE NEXT THING I KNOW
PARIS IS SWOOPING IN
LIKE A RECTILIAN VULTURE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
DIDN'T YOU HEAR THE WAY
THAT HE SAID THAT?
"I'LL BE ON THE BRIDGE
IF YOU NEED ME."
"IF YOU NEED ME."
NEELIX.
WHY DOESN'T HE JUST
PULL THE PLUG
ON THE HOLOGRAPHIC EMITTER
AND GET IT OVER WITH.
GET ME OUT OF THE WAY
SO HE CAN HAVE YOU ALL
TO HIMSELF?
NEELIX, YOU'RE OVERREACTING.
TOM'S BEEN VERY SUPPORTIVE.
AH, SO IT'S "TOM" NOW, IS IT?
YOU REALLY HAVE
NOTHING TO WORRY ABOUT.
WE'RE FRIENDS, THAT'S ALL.
IT'S NOT YOU I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
IT'S HIM.
HE'S JUST...
ONE BIG HORMONE
WALKING AROUND THE SHIP.
DON'T YOU SEE THE WAY
THAT HE LOOKS AT YOU?
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I AM NOT GOING TO ARGUE WITH YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING THAT EXISTS
ONLY IN YOUR IMAGINATION.
I KNOW YOU, NEELIX.
AND I KNOW YOU'RE AFRAID.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
I'LL BE HERE WITH YOU.
KE... KES...
I COULD BE IN HERE
A VERY LONG TIME.
YOU NEED TO GO ON
WITH YOUR LIFE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME.
NEELIX...
YOU SHOULD JUST LET ME DIE.
STOP THAT.
WE'RE GOING
TO GET THROUGH THIS TOGETHER.
VISITING HOURS
ARE OVER.
HE NEEDS REST.
WHEN CAN I COME BACK?
1700 HOURS,
NOT A MINUTE BEFORE.
I'LL SEE YOU THEN.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT GOING TO KISS YOU.
I'M ONLY ADJUSTING
THE RESTRAINT.
I'LL TRY TO CONTAIN
MY DISAPPOINTMENT.
Torres:
CAPTAIN, WE'VE COMPLETED OUR
DIAGNOSTIC ON THE ALIEN DEVICE.
IT APPEARS TO BE
MORE THAN A WEAPON.
IT'S ALSO A VERY
SOPHISTICATED
MEDICAL SCANNER
AND SURGICAL
INSTRUMENT.
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
IT USES A NEURAL RESONATOR
TO STUN THE VICTIM
WHILE A QUANTUM IMAGING SCANNER
BEGINS A MICROCELLULAR ANALYSIS
OF THE ENTIRE BODY.
THE AMOUNT OF INFORMATION
THIS THING CAN GATHER
PUTS A TRICORDER TO SHAME. YOU
FIRE THIS AT SOMEONE,
YOU LEARN EVERYTHING
ABOUT THEIR ANATOMY,
RIGHT DOWN TO THEIR
DNA SEQUENCING.
SO IT SOUNDS LIKE
WE'RE DEALING WITH ALIENS
WHO HAVE DEVELOPED A TECHNOLOGY
SPECIFICALLY DESIGNED
TO LOCATE AND EXTRACT ORGANS
FROM OTHER BEINGS. WHY?
Chakotay:
CAPTAIN.
THE ALIEN SHIP
HAS DROPPED OUT OF WARP.
IT'S APPROACHING
A LARGE ASTEROID.
ON SCREEN.
IT'S ENTERED THE ASTEROID,
CAPTAIN.
HOLD POSITION HERE.
MR. KIM?
I CAN'T SCAN
THE INTERIOR.
THE SURFACE STRATUM
IS MADE OF SOME SORT
OF NEUTRONIUM ALLOY.
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
A NATURAL FORMATION.
ARE YOU SAYING SOMEONE
BUILT THIS ASTEROID?
IT'S POSSIBLE.
ANY SIGN OF WEAPONS OR
DEFENSE SYSTEMS?
NEGATIVE.
I THINK I'VE LOCATED
WHERE THE ALIEN SHIP ENTERED.
THERE'S AN OPEN CRATER
ON THE ASTEROID.
LET'S SEE IT.
Paris:
THE ION TRAIL
FROM THE ALIEN SHIP
LEADS DIRECTLY INSIDE.
HOW LARGE IS THAT CRATER?
200 METERS
IN DIAMETER.
CAPTAIN,
MAY I SUGGEST
YOU CONSIDER CAREFULLY
WHAT YOU ARE ABOUT TO DO.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M ABOUT TO DO?
I COULD DESCRIBE TO YOU IN
DETAIL THE PSYCHOLOGICAL
OBSERVATIONS
I'VE MADE ABOUT YOU
OVER THE PAST FOUR YEARS
WHICH LEAD ME TO CONCLUDE
YOU ARE ABOUT TO TAKE
THIS SHIP INSIDE THE ASTEROID,
BUT SUFFICE IT TO SAY
I KNOW YOU QUITE WELL.
ONE OF THESE DAYS, I'M GOING
TO SURPRISE YOU, TUVOK.
BUT NOT TODAY.
I'VE ALREADY CONSIDERED
OTHER OPTIONS.
IF NEELIX HAS ANY CHANCE
OF SURVIVING
WE HAVE TO ACT FAST.
RED ALERT.
MR. PARIS, LAY IN A COURSE.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
MR. TUVOK,
MAXIMUM SHIELDS.
PHASERS AT THE READY.
CAPTAIN, I'M REDUCING POWER
TO THE AFT THRUSTERS ONLY.
THIS PASSAGEWAY IS GETTING
A LITTLE TOO NARROW
FOR MY TASTE.
USE YOUR DISCRETION,
MR. PARIS.
ANY SIGN OF THE VESSEL,
LIEUTENANT?
WE'RE STILL FOLLOWING
THE ION TRAIL
BUT ELECTROMAGNETIC INTERFERENCE
IS LIMITING OUR SENSOR RANGE.
I AM ONLY ABLE TO SCAN
500 METERS AHEAD OF US.
Chakotay:
ARE THERE ANY INDICATIONS
WE'RE BEING SCANNED
OR PROBED, MR. KIM?
Kim:
NOT YET.
DOCTOR?
DOCTOR,
I REQUIRE YOUR ASSISTANCE.
WHAT IS IT,
MR. NEELIX?
PLEASE, IT'S URGENT.
YES?
I HAVE AN ITCH.
AN ITCH?
JUST ABOVE MY LEFT EYEBROW.
( sighs )
A LITTLE HIGHER.
OH, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE QUITE WELCOME.
DOCTOR, WAIT. DON'T LEAVE.
I'M NOT LEAVING
MR. NEELIX
I'M SIMPLY GOING
BACK TO WORK.
I CAN'T SEE YOU OVER THERE.
I FEEL LIKE I'M ALL ALONE.
YOU ARE ALL ALONE.
I'M A HOLOGRAPHIC PROJECTION--
A PROJECTION WITH A LOT
OF WORK TO DO, I MIGHT ADD.
( chuckling )
THAT'S VERY AMUSING, DOCTOR.
BUT... UM...
I'M REALLY STARTING TO FEEL
A LITTLE, UH... TRAPPED IN HERE.
A LITTLE CLAUSTROPHOBIC MAYBE.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT TO DO.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN DO
EXCEPT LIE THERE AND BE QUIET.
I'M GOING TO LIE HERE
FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE
AREN'T I?
JUST STARING UP AT THE CEILING.
I'M NOT SURE I CAN TAKE THAT.
I REALLY NEED TO GET OUT
OF THIS RESTRAINT.
DOCTOR, I WANT YOU TO LET ME
OUT OF THIS THING
RIGHT NOW.
YOU KNOW THAT'S
IMPOSSIBLE.
I'M THE PATIENT.
I KNOW WHAT MY RIGHTS ARE.
I WANT TO BE RELEASED
FROM THIS RESTRAINT IMMEDIATELY.
IMMEDIATELY!
MR. NEELIX, YOU ARE ALIVE,
YOU ARE BREATHING
AND FOR THE MOMENT,
YOUR CONDITION IS STABLE.
THAT IS MORE THAN MOST PEOPLE
CAN SAY IN YOUR SITUATION.
NOW IT IS CRITICAL TO
YOUR RECOVERY
THAT YOU NOT SUBJECT YOURSELF
TO ANY ADDITIONAL STRESS.
TRY TO CALM DOWN.
DON'T TELL ME
TO CALM DOWN!
YOU'RE NOT THE ONE TRAPPED
IN A RESTRAINING FIELD WITH...
( gasping ) HOLO-LUNGS.
I DON'T THINK
THEY'RE WORKING.
I CAN'T... I CAN'T
GET ENOUGH OXYGEN.
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG.
YOU'RE HYPERVENTILATING.
TRY TO TAKE SLOW,
NATURAL BREATHS.
( choking )
I CAN'T.
( gasping )
I'M DYING.
LET ME OUT OF HERE.
WILL YOU HELP ME?
HELP ME.
HELP ME!
YOU'RE DOING JUST FINE,
MR. PARIS. JUST FINE.
THANKS, CAPTAIN.
SENSORS DETECT
A LARGE CHAMBER AHEAD.
WHAT THE HELL?
WE APPEAR TO BE SEEING
VOYAGER AND
THE ALIEN SHIP
REFLECTING OFF THE WALLS
OF THE CHAMBER.
Janeway:
CAN YOU DETERMINE WHICH SHIP
IS THE REAL ONE?
NO, CAPTAIN.
THE WALLS ARE EMANATING SEVERE
ELECTROMAGNETIC INTERFERENCE.
I CANNOT SCAN THEM DIRECTLY.
IT'S LIKE TRYING TO MOVE
THROUGH A HALL OF MIRRORS.
YOU NEVER NOW WHEN YOU'RE
GOING TO WALK INTO THE GLASS.
I'M STILL PICKING UP
THE ALIEN'S ION TRAIL.
MAYBE WE SHOULD FOLLOW THAT.
THEY MIGHT HAVE LEFT A FAKE
ION TRAIL TO LURE US IN HERE.
IT COULD LEAD US RIGHT
INTO ONE OF THOSE WALLS.
THAT'S A CHANCE WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE.
TUVOK, EXTEND THE DEFLECTORS
TO MAXIMUM RANGE.
IF WE DO RUN INTO SOMETHING,
IT'LL GIVE US
AN EXTRA MARGIN OF ERROR.
FOLLOW THE ION TRAIL,
MR. PARIS... SLOWLY.
MR. KIM, CONTINUOUS SCANS.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
I'LL DO WHAT I CAN
TO REASSURE HIM, DOCTOR.
GOOD. IF YOU DON'T MIND,
I'D LIKE YOU
TO REMAIN IN SICK BAY
SO YOU'RE HERE
WHEN HE WAKES UP.
OF COURSE.
( sighs )
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
ME?
YOU SEEM AGITATED ABOUT
SOMETHING.
OF COURSE I'M AGITATED.
THIS ENTIRE SITUATION
IS GETTING OUT OF CONTROL.
YOU MEAN NEELIX.
FIRST THEY TELL ME
THERE'S NO DOCTOR
SO I HAVE TO BE
ON CALL 24 HOURS A DAY.
THEN THEY TELL ME
THERE ARE NO NURSES
SO I HAVE NO ONE TO ASSIST ME.
I THOUGHT TOM PARIS
WAS ASSIGNED TO YOU.
LIKE I SAID...
NO ONE TO ASSIST ME.
AND NOW I HAVE A PATIENT WITH
SEVERE AND POSSIBLY LONG-TERM
EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS AND THERE'S
NO COUNSELOR ON BOARD.
I AM AN EMERGENCY MEDICAL
SUPPLEMENT--
A SUPPLEMENT, THAT'S ALL.
I WASN'T PROGRAMMED
FOR ANY OF THIS.
IT'S JUST...
UNACCEPTABLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
HOLOGRAPHIC ENGINEERING
BUT IF YOU WANT MY OPINION,
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN ACCEPTABLE.
YOU'VE BEEN REMARKABLE.
I'VE ONLY DONE WHAT
THE PROGRAM ALLOWS ME TO.
GIVE YOURSELF SOME CREDIT.
YOU SAVED HIS LIFE.
YOU DID--
NOT SOME PROGRAM.
IT MAY SEEM THAT WAY TO YOU.
THAT'S EXACTLY HOW IT SEEMS.
YOU'RE VERY...KIND.
HOW DOES A REAL DOCTOR LEARN
TO DEAL WITH PATIENTS'
EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS ANYWAY?
THEY LEARN FROM EXPERIENCE.
AREN'T YOU CAPABLE OF LEARNING?
I HAVE THE CAPACITY
TO ACCUMULATE
AND PROCESS DATA, YES.
THEN I GUESS
YOU'LL JUST HAVE TO LEARN...
LIKE THE REST OF US.
HAVE YOU EVER CONSIDERED
A CAREER IN MEDICINE?
( beeping )
NEELIX IS STARTING
TO REGAIN CONSCIOUSNESS.
LIEUTENANT, I'M PICKING UP
A MINOR POWER FLUCTUATION
IN THE WARP CORE.
COMPENSATE WITH
THE K.L.S. STABILIZER
NO EFFECT.
IN FACT, THE POWER LOSS
IS STARTING TO ACCELERATE.
Janeway to Torres.
What's going on down there?
SOME KIND OF POWER DRAIN.
I CAN'T LOCALIZE IT,
BUT...
WE'RE LOSING POWER
AT A RATE OF SEVEN PERCENT
PER MINUTE.
THE POWER DRAIN
IS COMING
FROM SOMEWHERE IN
THIS CHAMBER, CAPTAIN.
SOME KIND OF
DAMPENING FIELD.
IT'S BLEEDING ENERGY DIRECTLY
FROM THE WARP NACELLES.
B'ELANNA, SHUT DOWN
THE WARP CORE.
Go to emergency power.
NO EFFECT, CAPTAIN.
Keep me informed.
Bridge out.
CAN YOU PINPOINT THE SOURCE
OF THE DAMPENING FIELD?
IT APPEARS TO BE COMING
FROM 217 MARK 015.
DISTANCE 547 METERS.
TUVOK,
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN IF
WE LOCKED PHASERS
AND FIRED AT THE SOURCE?
THE WALLS OF THIS CHAMBER
REFLECT DIRECTED ENERGY.
THE PHASER BEAM WOULD RICOCHET
ALONG AN UNPREDICTABLE PATH
POSSIBLY IMPACTING
OUR SHIP IN THE PROCESS.
ALL RIGHT.
WE WON'T TRY THAT.
WELL, MAYBE WE SHOULD.
TUVOK, WHAT WOULD HAPPEN
IF WE REDUCED THE PHASER
POWER LEVEL TO A MINIMUM SETTING
AND SENT OUT
A CONTINUOUS BEAM?
THE PHASER WOULD CONTINUE
TO REFLECT OFF THE BULKHEADS
UNTIL IT ENCOUNTERED
A NONREFLECTIVE MATERIAL.
A NONREFLECTIVE MATERIAL--
LIKE THE REAL ALIEN SHIP.
SO, WE COULD USE THE PHASERS
LIKE A SEARCHLIGHT...
SCAN THE INTERIOR OF THE STATION
UNTIL WE FIND THE SHIP.
EXACTLY.
DO IT.
ADJUSTING PHASER AZIMUTH
TO 15 DEGREES.
WAIT A MINUTE. I THINK
I'VE FOUND THE REAL SHIP.
ON SCREEN.
MR. PARIS, BRING US WITHIN
TRANSPORTER RANGE OF THAT SHIP.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
I'M PICKING UP TWO LIFE SIGNS.
THEY'RE POWERING ENGINES.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER
ROOM THREE,
LOCK ON TO THOSE TWO LIFE SIGNS
AND BEAM THEM ABOARD.
SECURITY, MEET ME
IN TRANSPORTER ROOM THREE.
AYE, SIR.
YOU'RE ON
THE STARSHIP VOYAGER.
I'M CAPTAIN
KATHRYN JANEWAY
OF THE UNITED FEDERATION
OF PLANETS.
I AM DERETH...
OF THE VIIDIAN SODALITY.
YOU ATTACKED
ONE OF OUR CREW MEMBERS
AND YOU'VE LURED US
INTO THIS ASTEROID. WHY?
WE ARE GATHERING
REPLACEMENT ORGANS
AND SUITABLE BIOMATTER.
IT IS THE ONLY WAY WE HAVE
TO FIGHT THE PHAGE.
A VIRUS?
SOME KIND OF DISEASE?
YES.
IT ATTACKED OUR PEOPLE
OVER TWO MILLENNIA AGO.
IT CONSUMES OUR BODIES
DESTROYS OUR GENETIC CODES
AND CELLULAR STRUCTURES.
SO YOU HARVEST THE BODIES
OF OTHER BEINGS
TO REPLACE YOUR OWN TISSUES
AS THEY'RE CONSUMED
BY THIS... PHAGE?
OUR IMMUNOTECHNOLOGY
CANNOT KEEP UP.
THE PHAGE ADAPTS.
IT RESISTS ALL ATTEMPTS
TO DESTROY IT.
OUR SOCIETY
HAS BEEN RAVAGED.
THOUSANDS DIE EACH DAY.
THERE IS NO OTHER WAY
FOR US TO SURVIVE.
I HAVE A GREAT...
SYMPATHY FOR WHAT
YOUR RACE HAS ENDURED.
BUT I CANNOT ALLOW YOU
TO KEEP THE ORGANS YOU REMOVED
FROM ONE OF OUR CREW MEMBERS.
WE NEED THEM BACK IMMEDIATELY.
I'M AFRAID THAT ISN'T POSSIBLE.
I HAVE ALREADY
BIOCHEMICALLY ALTERED
THE AIR-BREATHING ORGANS
AND GRAFTED THEM
INTO MOTURA'S BODY.
THEY ARE A PART
OF HIM NOW.
HE IS MY HONATTA.
HIS TASK IS TO FIND
THE ORGANS I NEED FOR SURVIVAL.
WE...
WE TRY TO EXTRACT THEM
FROM THE DEAD...
BUT SOMETIMES,
WHEN THE NEED IS IMMEDIATE
MORE AGGRESSIVE ACTIONS
ARE REQUIRED.
SO NOW I AM LEFT WITH
THE SAME CHOICE YOU MADE:
WHETHER TO COMMIT MURDER
TO SAVE A LIFE
OR TO ALLOW MY OWN
CREWMAN TO DIE
WHILE YOU BREATHE AIR
THROUGH HIS LUNGS.
IT MUST BE IMPOSSIBLE
FOR YOU TO UNDERSTAND
HOW ANY CIVILIZED PEOPLE
COULD COME TO... THIS.
BEFORE THE PHAGE BEGAN
WE WERE KNOWN AS EDUCATORS
AND EXPLORERS--
A PEOPLE WHOSE GREATEST
ACHIEVEMENTS WERE ARTISTIC.
I, MYSELF, AM A SCULPTOR
OF NOTE ON MY WORLD.
ALL I CAN SAY IS THAT WHEN YOUR
ENTIRE EXISTENCE IS AT STAKE...
YOU DON'T HAVE TO EXPLAIN
YOURSELF, MOTURA.
IF THE CONSEQUENCE OF THIS ACT
IS A DEATH SENTENCE,
SO BE IT.
AT LEAST IT WILL PUT
AN END TO MY SUFFERING.
I CAN'T BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
YOUR PEOPLE HAVE GONE THROUGH.
THEY MAY HAVE FOUND A WAY
TO IGNORE THE MORAL IMPLICATIONS
OF WHAT YOU'RE DOING,
BUT I HAVE NO SUCH LUXURY.
I DON'T HAVE THE FREEDOM
TO KILL YOU TO SAVE ANOTHER.
MY CULTURE FINDS THAT
TO BE A REPREHENSIBLE
AND ENTIRELY UNACCEPTABLE ACT.
IF WE WERE CLOSER TO HOME
I WOULD LOCK YOU UP AND TURN YOU
OVER TO MY AUTHORITIES FOR TRIAL
BUT I DON'T EVEN HAVE
THAT ABILITY HERE
AND I AM NOT PREPARED TO CARRY
YOU FOREVER IN OUR BRIG.
SO I SEE NO OTHER ALTERNATIVE...
BUT TO LET YOU GO.
TAKE A MESSAGE
TO YOUR PEOPLE.
IF I EVER ENCOUNTER
YOUR KIND AGAIN
I WILL DO WHATEVER IS NECESSARY
TO PROTECT MY PEOPLE
FROM THIS... HARVESTING
OF YOURS.
ANY AGGRESSIVE ACTIONS
AGAINST THIS SHIP
OR IT'S CREW WILL BE MET
BY THE DEADLIEST FORCE.
IS THAT CLEAR?
UH... QUITE.
WAIT.
I WANT TO SEE
THIS CREWMAN OF YOURS.
THAT CAN SERVE
NO USEFUL PURPOSE.
MAYBE IT CAN.
OUR MEDICAL TECHNOLOGIES
MAY BE SUPERIOR TO THEIRS.
I CAN TELL YOU
FROM WHAT WE'VE OBSERVED OF THEM
THAT THEY ARE CONSIDERABLY
SUPERIOR.
SHE SPARED
MY LIFE--
OUR LIVES.
WE OWE IT TO THEM
TO SEE IF THERE'S
ANYTHING WE CAN DO
TO HELP HIM.
I'LL TAKE YOU TO HIM.
HIS SIMULATED ORGANS
ARE PRIMITIVE.
IT'S AMAZING
HE IS STILL ALIVE.
( sighs )
THIS IS SET
TO SCAN ONLY.
PROCEED...
CAREFULLY.
STRANGE.
ACCORDING TO MY READINGS,
YOU ARE NOT HERE.
BELIEVE ME,
I WISH I WEREN'T.
THE REST OF YOU ARE HEALTHY.
YOU ARE COMPATIBLE
FOR ORGAN TRANSPLANT.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WE'VE ALREADY CONSIDERED THIS.
TALAXIAN PHYSIOLOGY
IS DIFFERENT
FROM THAT OF ANYONE ELSE
ON THIS SHIP.
HIS IMMUNE SYSTEM WOULD
REJECT THEIR LUNGS IMMEDIATELY.
YOUR SURGICAL KNOWLEDGE
IS INFERIOR.
WE WILL SIMPLY ADAPT
HIS IMMUNOGENICITY.
IT WON'T BE
A PROBLEM.
WHICH OF YOU
WILL DONATE A LUNG?
ME.
Neelix: NO!
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
IT'S TOO DANGEROUS.
LET SOMEONE ELSE
DO IT.
NO. I WANT TO DO IT,
NEELIX.
I'M WILLING TO TAKE
THE RISK.
BESIDES, YOU'VE DONE
SO MUCH FOR ME.
LET ME GIVE YOU
SOMETHING ONCE.
JUST FOR ONCE.
ALL RIGHT.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO SAMPLING YOUR COOKING,
MR. NEELIX.
YOU MEAN, I CAN KEEP
MY KITCHEN?
WELL, AT LEAST UNTIL WE GET
THE REPLICATORS BACK ON LINE.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
AND, CAPTAIN...
I'LL SEE YOU AT BREAKFAST.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
THE ALIENS HAVE SUCCESSFULLY
TRANSPLANTED
ONE OF KES'S LUNGS INTO NEELIX.
THE DAMPENING FIELD
HAS BEEN DEACTIVATED
AND I HAVE ALLOWED THEM
TO BEAM BACK TO THEIR VESSEL.
WE ARE RESUMING A COURSE HOME.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THE OPERATION WAS A SUCCESS.
NEELIX IS ASLEEP AND
BREATHING ON HIS OWN NOW...
WITH YOUR LUNG.
I FEEL A LITTLE LIGHT-HEADED.
THAT WILL PASS.
YOU'LL SOON ADAPT
TO DIMINISHED LUNG CAPACITY.
I SPOKE TO THE CAPTAIN
ABOUT YOU.
SHE'S GIVEN ME PERMISSION
TO BEGIN TRAINING YOU
AS A MEDICAL ASSISTANT.
YOU'LL BE A BACKUP
FOR MR. PARIS
OR, POSSIBLY, A REPLACEMENT.
THAT IS, ASSUMING
YOU'RE INTERESTED.
OF COURSE I'M INTERESTED.
WHEN DO WE START?
WE'LL BEGIN YOUR LESSONS AS SOON
AS YOU'VE FULLY RECOVERED.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
THANK YOU.
YOU'VE GIVEN ME
A LOT TO THINK ABOUT.