JANEWAY:
Personal Log,
Stardate 48546.2.
Our journey home
is several weeks old now,
and I have begun to notice
in my crew, and in myself,
a subtle change as the reality
of our situation settles in.
Here in the Delta Quadrant,
we are virtually
the entire family of man.
We are more than a crew,
and I must find a way
to be more than a Captain
to these people...
but it's not clear to me
exactly how to begin.
At the Academy, we're taught
that a Captain is expected
to maintain a certain distance.
Until now, I have
always been comfortable
with that distance.
TORRES:
Captain, I...
I didn't realize there was
an inspection scheduled.
Not an inspection,
Lieutenant.
A stroll.
We should have the warp drive
up and running by 0900 hours.
Recalibrating
the reactant injectors
is the only thing
we have left to do.
Carry on.
Maybe this is
just the way it works.
Maybe the distance
is necessary.
Maybe more than ever now,
they need me
to be larger than life.
I only wish
I felt larger than life.
Computer, delete last sentence.
Gentlemen.
As you were.
So has Neelix concocted
anything interesting
this morning?
There's an ancient
Chinese curse, Captain--
"May you live
in interesting times."
Mealtime
is always interesting
now that Neelix
is in the kitchen.
We shouldn't judge him
too harshly.
He is helping us
conserve replicator energy.
And I'm sure
the gastrointestinal
problems will go away,
as soon as our systems
get used to his, uh...
gourmet touch.
( chuckling )
Well, see you at duty call.
We should have
asked her to join us.
Ensigns don't invite
Captains to sit down.
Why not?
Because they don't.
Well, what's wrong with
showing a little courtesy?
Captains don't want courtesy.
They want respect.
That's why they don't get chummy
with the lower ranks.
Well, who else
is she supposed
to get chummy with out here?
There aren't many other
Captains and Admirals
for her to talk to.
If she wants to sit with us,
she'll ask us to join her.
That's the way
it's done.
I think you're working
from an old rule book, Paris.
Neelix?
( liquid bubbling )
NEELIX:
Captain!
May I say,
you look beautiful this morning.
Is that a new color lipstick?
No, no, it's the same
color I always wear.
Well, perhaps it's
just the way the glow
of the food heater lamps
hits you,
but you look wonderful.
Not to suggest
you don't always
look wonderful.
Neelix, do we have
any coffee left?
No, but we have
something even better.
I don't want something
even better, I want coffee.
It's made from
a proteinaceous seed
I discovered
on an expedition...
Never mind.
I'll use one of my
replicator rations
for coffee.
That would not
be appropriate, Captain.
I beg your pardon?
You need to set
an example for the crew.
Well, thank you
for reminding me.
You're welcome.
I mean, after all,
if you want the crew
to begin to accept
natural food alternatives
instead of further depleting
our energy reserves,
you need to encourage them
by your own choices, don't you?
Fine. Give me your
even-better-than-coffee
substitute.
And how about some
Takar loggerhead eggs
with that this morning?
Just... coffee.
It's a tiny bit richer blend
than you're used to,
but you'll learn
to love it.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Janeway.
On my way. Janeway out.
Tomorrow maybe.
Ah.
Yes, Commander?
There was no need
for you to come to
the Bridge, Captain.
Yes, there was.
I just wanted to alert you
to a nebula
we've picked up on
long-range sensors.
Put it on screen.
Magnify.
TUVOK:
There are unusually high levels
of omicron particles
within this nebula, Captain.
Are you thinking we could
collect these omicron particles
to provide an additional
antimatter reserve, Lieutenant?
Precisely.
Senior Bridge Officers,
report for duty.
Commander, set a new course.
There's coffee in that nebula.
Exploring this nebula
should raise some spirits
around here,
don't you think, Commander?
No way to go but up.
You're closer
to the crew than I am.
How bad is it?
There's a nuanka--
A period of mourning
that everyone's
going through.
It's a natural reaction.
I'm worried about them.
I wish we had
a Counselor on board,
but the nature of our mission
didn't require one.
We talk to animals.
It's a Native
American tradition.
Animals?
Our own counselors.
We're taught that
an animal guide
accompanies us
through life.
Basically, it's what Carl
Jung thought he invented
when he came up with
his "active imagination"
technique in 1932,
but we'd been doing
pretty much the same
thing for centuries.
Is there a different
animal guide for everyone?
Actually, yes.
Let me guess.
Yours is a bear.
( chuckling )
Why do you say that?
You strike me
as the bear type.
Thank you.
The bear is a very
powerful animal.
It has great pokattah,
but he's not
my animal guide.
The creature that guides us
doesn't define who we are.
It merely chooses
to be with us.
Okay. If not a bear,
then what?
I can't tell you that.
It would offend
my animal guide
if I spoke its name.
But he guides you well?
Actually, it's female.
But, yes, she usually
guides me very well.
Can one just choose
her own animal guide?
It's not quite that simple.
PARIS:
Captain,
we are approaching
the perimeter of the nebula.
Slow to one-third impulse.
If you're interested,
I'll be glad to teach you
how to contact
your animal guide.
You've got a date.
Analysis, Mr. Kim.
KIM:
Seven AU's in diameter.
Sensors are picking up
intermittent gamma
and thermal emissions.
Nothing our shields
can't handle.
Mr. Paris, any problems
for navigation?
I'm showing
mostly hydrogen, helium,
and hydroxyl radicals.
Some local dust nodules.
I don't see them
giving us any trouble.
Mr. Tuvok, can you find us
a rich deposit of omicron
particles in there?
A significant concentration
appears to exist
approximately
64 million kilometers
inside the perimeter.
Set coordinates.
Aye, Captain.
Engines at one-
quarter impulse.
Engage.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Tuvok to Kim.
Mr. Kim, that is a comment
we would prefer not to hear
from a Senior Officer
on the Bridge.
It makes the Junior
Officers nervous.
Yes, sir.
PARIS:
Density has increased
to 42 percent.
Cause?
Not sure.
We seem to be drawing
some interstellar dust
toward us.
Engineering, could
the magnetic field
from our impulse engines
be attracting this dust?
It's a good possibility,
Captain.
I'm showing the dust with
a return force ratio of 4.1.
Recommend we shut down impulse
and go to thrusters.
Acknowledged.
Engage thrusters.
Ahead slow.
Density still increasing.
Up by 70 percent now.
Mr. Tuvok?
The level
of resistance
poses no danger to the hull
at this time, Captain.
How far to your omicron
particle deposits?
12,400 kilometers.
Maintain
course and...
Report!
We're at a
dead stop now.
Shutting down thrusters.
We seem to have
encountered
an energy barrier.
Is it natural
or artificial?
We're not reading
any directed energy source
down here, Captain.
My guess is
it's a natural phenomenon.
How far are we
from the particles, Lieutenant?
Just over
7,000 kilometers.
It's conceivable
this energy barrier
is related to those particles.
Mr. Kim, if you could get
a transporter beam
through the barrier...
Can't do it, Captain.
The thoron emissions
of the barrier
would interfere with
the transporter signal.
Ms. Torres,
do we have enough power
to take the ship
through the barrier?
The barrier appears
to be only 50 meters deep.
A four-second burst
at maximum thrusters
ought to do it.
All right.
Maximum shields.
Engage full thrusters
for four seconds
and then drop to one-quarter.
Acknowledged.
Engaging thrusters.
What do you make of it,
Mr. Tuvok?
I am unable to offer
an identification, Captain.
( whispers ):
Kim to Tuvok.
In other words,
you've never seen
anything like it?
Oh, I promise
not to tell the Junior Officers.
PARIS:
Captain,
the breach we just made,
where we penetrated the field--
It just closed behind us.
Kes! Oh! Now look
what she's
gotten us into!
Do all nebulas look like that?
I wouldn't know.
I'm smart enough
to go around nebulas
when I encounter them.
These people are
natural-born explorers, Neelix.
These people are natural-born
idiots if you ask me.
They don't appreciate
what they have here.
This ship
is the match of any vessel
within a hundred light years,
and what do they do with it?
"Well, let's see
if we can't find
"some space anomaly today
that might rip it apart!"
I don't think
the Captain is an idiot.
She cares a great deal
about her crew.
You don't care a great deal
about your crew
and introduce them to
the specter of death
at every opportunity.
And I speak as a member
of that crew now.
I'm not sure I would have
wanted you to come along
had I known that
this is what we...
I think it's wonderful.
Wonderful?
If I were Captain,
I'd open every crack
in the universe
and peek inside,
just like
Captain Janeway does.
I don't deny the romantic...
quality of this sort
of... casting about.
I wouldn't exactly
call it wonderful.
Although...
it's getting more
wonderful by the minute.
I've never kissed anyone
inside a nebula before.
What did I tell you?
Red Alert.
Whatever they are,
they're passing right
through our shields.
Try reversing
the shield polarity.
Mr. Tuvok?
They appear to be made up
of a non-reactive
material that our sensors
do not recognize,
Captain.
Clarify. Are we under attack?
Uncertain.
There is no indication
of directed fire.
Torres to Bridge.
Go ahead.
These things
are sticking to the hull.
And I'm showing a drain
on our energy reserves.
A drain?
Why would we be losing energy?
I'm not sure, Captain.
They seem to be drawing it
right through the shield grid
along the hull.
We've lost five percent
of our energy reserves.
Recommend we shut down
all non-essential systems.
Do it.
Reversing shield polarity
hasn't had any effect.
Energy reserves
are down eight percent.
This is not
what I had in mind.
Mr. Paris, take us back
through the energy barrier
and out of here.
Reversing course.
Full thrusters.
Thrusters firing.
We're not penetrating
the energy barrier this time.
Sensors show a buildup
of magneside dust
along the outer rim
of the barrier.
Engineering,
I need more power.
We can't go back to impulse,
Captain.
That's how our problems started.
Our best chance
is to burn the aft thrusters
beyond the recommended limits.
Proceed.
Acknowledged. Accelerating
deuterium to rear thrusters.
We have a complement
of 38 photon torpedoes
at our disposal, Captain.
And no way to replace them
after they're gone.
Aft thrusters
at 105 percent.
115 percent.
Barrier still holding.
We need something else.
Give me a two-second blast
from the forward phaser bank.
Firing phasers.
The barrier
is undamaged, Captain.
Ready a photon.
Mr. Paris,
assuming we can breach
the energy barrier,
it's likely to close as
fast as the first time.
I'll be riding the tail
of our torpedo, Captain.
TUVOK:
Torpedo is loaded.
Align coordinates
along ship's heading.
Coordinates set.
Fire.
50,000 kilometers
to the perimeter.
I'm having trouble
navigating
through
the energy currents.
It's as thick as
a Toarian ice storm out there.
35,000 kilometers to perimeter.
Energy reserves
are still falling.
15,000 kilometers.
We've cleared the central mass.
Stand down Red Alert.
Take us to 2,000 kilometers
off the perimeter
and hold position.
Get a sample of that matter
off the hull
for Lieutenant Torres
to analyze.
I'd like to know
what it was
that humbled every
defense system on this ship.
How much of our energy reserves
did we lose, Ensign?
11 percent, Captain.
I'm just going to have
to give up coffee.
That's all there is to it.
Dark enough for you?
What?
Get up, Harry. There's
something you got to see.
See?
How'd you get in here?
You'd be surprised
the things you learn in prison.
MacAllister--
James Mooney MacAllister.
The guy never slept.
He'd be studying
his algorithms until dawn,
and the only way
I could get any sleep
was to wear a mask.
You could've
changed roommates.
Are you kidding?
MacAllister
got me through
fourth year
quantum chemistry.
Besides, I got used
to wearing it.
Something about it
that reminds me
of being in the womb.
Harry, in order to be
reminded of something,
you have to first...
I remember being
in my mother's womb.
Right.
I do.
So what is it
you have to show me?
Nothing that's
going to compare
to that memory
of your mother's womb.
Computer, activate
holodeck program Paris-3.
( male guffawing )
MALE:
Hey, it's Tom.
Welcome, Tom, welcome.
Hey, Tom,
how you doing?
PARIS:
What do you think, Harry?
What is it,
a French bistro?
This is where I spent
most of my second
semester at the Academy.
I chose the Starfleet base
outside of Marseilles
for my physical training.
I always had a thing
about the French.
And the French
always had a thing
about you,
Monsieur Thomas.
And with a name
like Paris,
and a face like that,
how could anyone
resist, huh?
Sandrine, this is my friend,
Harry Kim.
Enchanté.
Sandrine owns the place.
It's been in her family
over 600 years.
WOMAN:
Tommy.
It's about time.
I've been waiting for you.
This is Ricky.
I include her in all
my holo-programs.
RICKY:
Hi.
Mmm...
Your friend the gigolo
wouldn't leave me alone.
It's what I do, Tom.
Nothing personal.
French father, Daliwakan mother.
She just sits there
and waits for you, huh?
Like a little
puppy dog.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
Oh, really?
I thought you
liked your women
with a little bite.
Everyone knows
about your bite, Sandrine.
It's when you start
sucking blood they get scared.
Monsieur, can I get you
something to drink?
Just a cup of tea.
Harry, this is France.
Uh, break open a bottle
of that '46 Saint Emilion
you save behind the bar for me.
I don't like to drink
this late at night.
I get an acid heartburn.
Harry, it's holographic wine.
It doesn't
give you acid.
Try to get in
the mood, huh?
Sorry.
I learned a great deal
that semester at the Academy.
Most of it
right here.
Oui-- And most of it
from me.
I found this place
just after my
pocket was picked
walking by the harbor.
Somebody picked
your pocket on Earth?
Oh, they just do
it for tourists.
They give it back.
Most of the time.
MAN:
Nine ball
in the corner pocket.
You see that pool
table, Harry?
The table at Sandrine's
at Marseilles
has attracted the world's
greatest hustlers
throughout the centuries.
I thought it might
be fun to program in
some of the great
players to shoot with.
Eight ball in the cross side.
Gaunt Gary,
Ames Pool Hall,
New York City, 1953.
They say that
he hustled
the great Willie
Moscone himself.
Moscone?
Was he some famous
billiard player?
Game is pool, kid. Pool.
I don't suppose you'd care
to wager a fin on a game or two?
Oh, he's not ready
for you yet, Gary.
Let me teach him
a few tricks first.
Watch out
for him, kid.
He can swallow your wallet
without ever losing his smile.
I'll keep it in mind.
What's a fin?
I'm not sure.
Some old kind of
Scandinavian currency.
Come on.
I'll rack them up.
You pick out a cue.
Harry, this is my idea of home.
My little piece of Earth
out here in the Delta Quadrant.
You shrug it off--
Or you like to make
the rest of us think
you're shrugging it off--
But you miss it
too, don't you?
What?
Home.
Your shot, Harry.
Computer, activate emergency
medical holographic program.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Why do you always
have to say that?
I can only speculate about
my programmer's motives.
Perhaps he thought
I might be summoned
for... important reasons.
Under the circumstances,
don't you think
you really ought to
change your program?
Now, there's
an interesting concept--
A hologram
that programs himself.
What would I do
with that ability?
Create a family,
raise an army...
I know a little about
holographic programming.
I could probably
reprogram you.
That makes me feel
particularly confident.
Has anyone ever told you,
you have a lousy attitude?
If you don't like
the doctor's attitude,
there's a man sitting
at a console
in the Jupiter Station
Holo-programming Center
you can write to.
His name is Zimmerman.
He looks a lot
like me, actually.
Now, not that I don't
enjoy the repartee,
but was there a reason
you stopped in?
I need a second opinion on this.
Who gave you
the first opinion?
I gave it to myself.
It's a sample of residue
we picked up in a nebula.
A nebula?
What were we doing in a nebula?
No, wait, don't tell me.
We were investigating.
That's all we do around here.
Why pretend
we're going home at all?
All we're going to do
is investigate
every cubic millimeter
of this Quadrant, aren't we?
The molecules are isolinear.
No polycyclic
structures, but...
But this is what brought
you to me, isn't it?
The nucleogenic
peptide bonds.
Is it some kind
of phospholipid fiber?
And you were doing so well.
Now... I suspect
it's something
far more interesting than that.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Repair crews have degaussed
the hull, Captain.
Good. Let's plan
an 0700 departure.
What's this?
My medicine bundle.
I've never shown it
to anyone before.
After what you said
this morning,
I thought
it was important
to let you see.
Will it help me find
my animal guide?
Eventually, you'll
have to assemble
your own medicine bundle,
but this will allow me
to assist you
in your quest for a guide.
Now?
Now.
A blackbird's wing...
a stone from
the river...
an akoonah.
"Akoonah"?
My ancestors used
psychoactive herbs
to assist their
vision quests.
Now they're no longer necessary.
Our scientists have found
more modern ways
to facilitate the search
for animal guides.
Place your
hand on it.
And concentrate
on the stone.
A-koo-chee-moya.
We are far from the sacred
places of our grandfathers.
We are far from the
bones of our people,
but perhaps there is
one powerful being
who will embrace
this woman
and give her the
answers she seeks.
Allow your eyes to close.
Breathe to feel the
light in your belly
and let it expand
until the light
is everywhere.
Prepare yourself
to leave this room
and this ship,
and return to a place
where you were the most content
and peaceful you have ever been.
You can see all around you
and hear the sounds
of this place.
( bird squawking )
I know this place.
It's...
You must not discuss with me
what you see,
or you will offend
your animal guide.
As you continue to look around,
you will become aware
of other life
that shares
this place with you.
It will be the first animal
you see.
That is the one
you will speak to.
Do you see an animal?
Yes.
Speak to it.
What do I say?
You know what you want to ask.
( door chimes )
I'm sorry.
I should've asked the computer
for no interruptions.
Come in.
The Commander was introducing me
to my animal guide.
I hope
that you have
better luck with yours
than I had with mine.
B'Elanna's the
only one I know
who tried to kill
her animal guide.
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but the Doctor and I
have come up with a rather
surprising analysis
of the matter
left on the hull.
It's organic.
Microscopic life-forms
from the nebula.
That's not what I mean.
The samples are clearly
organic elements
of a much larger life-form.
It appears, Captain,
that this nebula
is not a nebula at all.
DOCTOR:
I'm curious, Captain.
Exactly what
are you looking for?
I need to know if we did serious
harm to this life-form.
Let's see--
You ran your ship through it,
fired phasers at it,
and blew a hole in it
with a photon torpedo.
I'd say it's a pretty good
chance that you...
Computer, mute audio.
Isolate that concentration
of omicron particles
we were trying to get to.
That would be
right here.
JANEWAY:
Mr. Tuvok?
I'm afraid the
concentration
of particles
is far lower than I
originally observed.
Furthermore, it appears
that many of the particles
have now moved outside
the energy barrier.
Is it possible they're leaking
out through the breach we made?
That would be a
logical conclusion.
It's also a logical conclusion
that all of the phenomena
we've encountered
were actually this life-form's
natural defense systems.
The way the barrier was
protecting the omicron particles
almost suggests we were
entering a vital organ.
So, it seems very clear
that we've severely hurt
an innocent life-form.
How do we repair
the harm we've done?
PARIS:
Uh, Captain?
Computer, resume audio.
How kind of you.
You may be interested to know
that the analysis
of the organic sample
suggested this life-form
has the capacity to regenerate.
The process may simply
need a helping hand.
Any ideas how we could
stimulate regeneration?
Lieutenant Torres
has the answer.
I do?
You were the one
who first observed
that this life-form has
a nucleogenic structure.
If the life-form has
a nucleogenic structure...
nucleonic radiation
ought to assist
its healing process.
A nucleonic beam along
the edges of the breach
should theoretically
promote regeneration.
Bravo.
Commander, take us
to Yellow Alert
and advise the crew
that we're going to reenter
the life-form.
Mr. Kim, review all systems
in light of our first experience
and see if you can
provide
new safeguards.
Tuvok, your job is to find
some modification of the shields
that will hold off
this life-form's
natural defense systems.
We begin at 1300 hours.
Dismissed.
The bantan is a little
on the spicy side.
Kes grows them herself
in the hydroponic garden.
Don't eat any of the little pink
things and you'll be fine.
CHAKOTAY:
All personnel
report to stations.
Yellow Alert.
Now what?
Neelix to Chakotay.
We're very busy up here, Neelix.
What do you need?
This Yellow Alert business--
I was just starting...
Sorry. We found out that the
nebula is actually a life-form
and we've got to go back in to
repair some damage we did to it.
Chakotay out.
Go back in? Hello?
Well, that's it!
I've had it!
Neelix...
No!
I'm going to
the Captain about this.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Captain, I understand
that this nebula
we've discovered
is some kind of monster?
Not a monster, Neelix,
but it is a life-form.
Excuse me if I sound crazy,
because someone may have been
playing a joke on me,
but you aren't planning
to take us back into the belly
of this beast, are you?
No joke.
Why?
Because we hurt it
and we have to help it recover.
I did not come on board
this ship to be
a veterinarian, Captain.
And I thought you were
a man of unlimited talents.
I just reached my limit.
So if you don't mind,
Kes and I will wait on board
my little vessel
for you to return.
All our crews are busy
preparing for this mission.
I'm not pulling them
off their duties
to prepare your ship for launch,
and I'm not going to drop you
off on the side of the road
every time we hit a bump.
When we're finished,
if you want to leave,
that's your business,
but for the moment,
find yourself
a seat with a good view
because, just like Jonah
and the whale, you're going in.
Is that final?
Dismissed.
That's a Starfleet expression
for "get out."
Jonah?
Whale?
Approaching the perimeter.
Disengage impulse engines.
Impulse engines off-line.
Engage thrusters, one-third.
Thrusters engaged.
Red Alert.
( alarm blaring )
TUVOK:
Shields are up.
Adaptive harmonics
are operational.
Density is already
more than double
what we encountered
last time.
EM hull pressure is approaching
dangerous levels, Captain.
Mr. Kim?
If my research is right,
releasing positive ions
through the nacelles
should repel
some of the dust out there.
Without causing further harm
to the creature?
I believe so, Captain.
Very well.
Ion release confirmed.
Ambient density is dropping.
Hull pressure
is decreasing also.
Hold your course.
TUVOK:
14,000 kilometers
to the breach.
I can see it.
Magnify.
Engineering,
ready your nucleonic beam.
Ready and awaiting your orders,
Captain.
Mr. Paris,
bring us into position.
Coming about 40 degrees.
Report!
We're being hit by some
kind of multi-polar charges.
They're not like anything
we saw the first time.
Shields at 87 percent.
Will they hold?
The polarity of each charge
is rotating so quickly,
the shields cannot compensate.
We've lost
the rear driver coil assembly.
Inertial dampers are off-line.
I'm losing control.
Hold on!
Engineering, initiate emergency
shutdown of all thrusters.
TORRES:
Captain, the only way
we can shut down all thrusters
is to vent the deuterium
into space.
We can't afford
to lose all that fuel.
We have no choice.
Do it!
Acknowledged.
Cutting thrusters.
Inertial dampers
are still off-line.
Reset IDF baseline at 3-0-0
and reinitialize.
Field processors
coming back on line.
Inertial damping restored.
All stop.
Damage report.
KIM:
Electro-plasma leaks
reported on Deck 14.
Repair crews are
being dispatched.
Otherwise, we seem
to be in one piece.
I believe the optical data
network is down, Ensign.
Yes, sir.
I'll get right on it.
14 injuries reported, Captain.
None serious.
Have any idea where we are,
Mr. Paris?
Approximately 70,000 kilometers
from our former position.
Deeper inside the creature
than before.
Let's hope it has
a slow digestive process.
Yes, ma'am.
We need to get back
to the wound
without causing a response
from its defense systems.
Suggestions?
It seems to be leaving us alone
now that we've cut off
all propulsion systems.
Maybe that's what cues it
to respond.
If I'm right, we might
be able to get back
without engaging any engines.
No engines?
We've been reading these
swirling energy currents
since we first got here.
When we thought
it was a nebula,
we weren't looking
for any pattern.
We thought they were
just random eddies.
But now I'm wondering
if these currents
might be some kind of
a circulatory system.
Mr. Kim, are you showing omicron
particles in these currents?
Affirmative, Captain.
If the currents are distributing
omicron energy
throughout the life-form,
the circulatory system
might pass right by that wound.
We could get in one
of those currents
and surf back.
Use the reaction
control thrusters
in drift mode only, Mr. Paris.
Aye, Captain.
We're on our way.
Speed-- All of 200 k.p.h.
NEELIX:
Time for refreshment.
Ailis pâté,
Felada onion crisps,
stuffed Cardaway leaves.
I appreciate the thought,
Neelix,
but this is hardly the time.
As the morale officer
on this ship,
I insist that a break
in the workload
is both healthy
and necessary.
Go on, Mr. Vulcan.
It might even
help you loosen up.
Or not.
May I ask when you
became morale officer?
Oh, just a few minutes ago,
when I sensed crew morale
might be especially low.
Mine certainly was.
We were in a free fall
at the time.
Cooking always helps
Neelix to unwind.
Yes, and after
we stabilized
I certainly needed to unwind.
So it seemed to me,
I had a choice to either
come up here and say,
"I told you so"...
No.
or to try to do
something constructive
to help out
in my own humble manner.
Try the stuffed
Cardaway leaves.
They're irresistible.
Now, as your new
morale officer,
I thought it might be fun
for us all to sing
a few songs together.
Don't push it, Neelix.
Captain?
Well done,
Mr. Paris.
Take us gently out
of the current.
Stay in RCS drift mode.
Aye, Captain.
Ms. Torres, prepare
your nucleonic beam.
We're ready down here, Captain.
Let's give the wound
two doses to start.
Five bursts
at a two-second interval.
Now.
Analysis.
Scanners are showing
the regeneration rate up
only .04 percent.
I don't know
what we can hope to accomplish
if this is the best we can do.
The breach may simply be
too large to seal.
This is the Doctor speaking.
Please activate your monitor
to the emergency medical
holographic channel.
I believe I may have
a suggestion that will help.
Since no one had the courtesy
to turn me off
after my last consultation,
I've had the opportunity
to observe your progress--
Or lack of same.
A slight alteration of your
treatment plan is necessary.
As inspiration, I've drawn
on an ancient medical technique
known as a suture.
"Suture"?
Before the advent
of laser technology,
surgical fiber was used
to stitch together a wound
to allow it to heal naturally.
How does that help us?
Your ship's energy systems
are compatible
with this life-form's omicron
particles, are they not?
That's right.
Then it is very likely
that this vessel could
serve the life-form's needs
in much the same manner
as a suture.
By allowing the ship to serve
as an energy conduit
across the wound,
the life-form should be able
to regenerate itself
more rapidly.
And how are we supposed
to get the ship into the wound
without getting the hell
beat out of us again?
That's your problem, not mine.
Doctor out.
That's sort of like
asking a hurt dog
not to bite you
while you tend to its wounds.
You like dogs, Mr. Paris?
Yes, ma'am.
I always had a dog.
I like dogs, too.
When I had to clean out a cut
on my dog's leg,
I needed to create
a little diversion first
to take her mind off it.
Mr. Kim, prepare
a class-4 microprobe.
Aye, Captain.
Lieutenant, if I gave you a
short burst from our thrusters,
would it be enough
for you to maneuver
into the breach in ten seconds?
I'd feel better
if I had 20.
Once we launch that probe
as a diversion,
you might have ten,
maybe even less than that.
Ten sounds good.
Mr. Kim, status?
Microprobe is loaded
and ready.
Set coordinates for launch
at 160 mark 70.
Cut power after 500 meters.
I don't want to hurt
this life-form again.
Acknowledged.
Engineering, I'll need
a one-second burst
from our aft thrusters
on my order.
Standing by.
Launch microprobe.
Thrusters.
Firing!
Reading mono-polar charges,
high frequency.
Shields at 75 percent
and holding.
Maintain position.
Engineering, direct
two nucleonic beams
fore and aft-- Parallel
to the central axis of the ship.
Acknowledged.
Beam engaged.
Captain, I'm showing a rapid
growth pattern along the wound.
Regenerative matter approaching
from both directions
at just under 500 kilometers
per hour.
Hold position.
Captain, the shields are only
designed to withstand...
I'm aware of that, Mr. Tuvok.
Hold position!
Regenerative matter approaching.
Range...?
30 kilometers--
Fore and aft.
Engineering,
ready full thrusters.
Mr. Paris?
Just tell me when.
Regenerative matter
at 20 kilometers.
Fifteen... ten...
Disengage nucleonic beam.
Fire thrusters.
Thrusters engaged.
Now, Mr. Paris.
40,000 kilometers
to the perimeter.
30,000.
The life-form's
regeneration rate
is up 40 percent, Captain.
Looks like it's well on the way
to closing that wound.
We've cleared the central mass.
( sighs )
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We set out
to augment our energy reserves
and wound up depleting them
by over 20 percent.
As a result,
we've set a new course
for a planet
14 light-years away
that Neelix says might have
compatible energy sources
to offer us.
It is out of our way,
but circumstances offer
few alternatives.
So much for raising spirits.
Turning in
for the night, Captain?
Actually, I'm going
to talk to an animal
and then turn in.
Something Commander
Chakotay taught me.
Supposed to be
quite therapeutic.
You might want
to ask him about it.
I will.
Captain...
What is it, Ensign?
Well, I don't mean
to be out of place,
but if you'd care
to join us,
you'd be welcome.
Join you where?
Come on, Tommy.
Let's get out of here.
Easy, honey.
I'm setting the Indian up
for the big hustle.
But he's beating you.
Yeah, that's exactly what
he's supposed to think too.
As you were.
Well... this is remarkable.
Mr. Kim tells me this is
your doing, Mr. Paris.
Ah... yeah.
It's just a little
diversion, Captain.
One always knows
when a woman of good breeding
enters the room.
Ma chérie...
may I request
your favorite song
so that we may dance,
before I take you
to my private felucca
on the wharf
and make
passionate love to you?
Uh... I'm sorry.
If I had some kind of warning
that you were coming...
You would have changed it, and
I would have missed all the fun.
( chuckling )
I just don't know
what the dolls see
in a gigolo, do you?
Now me, I got a whole
different approach to women.
Treat a lady like a tramp
and a tramp like a lady.
Never fails.
Paris, did you program
this guy?
Yeah. Why?
He's a pig
and so are you.
( clears throat )
Almost never.
Is this pool or billiards?
Uh, pool.
Right.
Pool's the one
with the pockets.
Would you mind
if I gave it a try?
Reculez-vous!
Give the handsome
young woman some room.
Tell me, does she have,
uh, money?
Commander Chakotay, your stick?
It's called a cue, Captain.
Cue.
All right.
So what do we do?
Do I go first?
( astonished exclamations )
Solids.
I saw that coming
a mile away, didn't you?
Ah, you've got a lot
to learn, jeune homme.
But then... I've got
a lot to teach.
Eight ball in the side pocket.
JANEWAY:
A-koo-chee-moya.
We are far
from the sacred places
of our grandfathers and from
the bones of our people,
but perhaps there is
one powerful being
who will embrace this good crew
and give them
the answer they seek.