CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 48579.4.
THE CREW HAS BEEN SCANNING
CONSTANTLY FOR ANOMALIES
THAT MIGHT HELP US
SHORTEN OUR JOURNEY HOME.
ENSIGN KIM HAS REPORTED
AN EXCITING DISCOVERY--
A SUBSPACE DISTURBANCE
WHICH MAY BE A WORMHOLE.
LET'S SEE WHAT YOU HAVE,
MR. KIM.
THERE. IT'S REGISTERING
ONLY ON SUBSPACE BANDS.
WE DON'T EVEN HAVE IT
ON LONG-RANGE SENSORS YET.
VERTERON EMANATIONS.
TUNNELING SECONDARY PARTICLES.
IT CERTAINLY LOOKS
LIKE A WORMHOLE.
BUT IS IT STABLE ENOUGH
FOR US TO ENTER,
AND IF IT IS,
WHERE DOES IT LEAD?
THERE IS, OF COURSE,
A 75% CHANCE
A WORMHOLE WILL NOT LEAD
TO THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
VERY TRUE, BUT YOU CAN ALSO SAY
THERE'S A ONE-IN-FOUR CHANCE
IT WILL. THOSE AREN'T BAD ODDS.
ANY ANALYSIS
YET, ENSIGN?
WE'RE TOO FAR AWAY.
WE'D HAVE TO BE
WITHIN 1,000 KILOMETERS
TO GET A DETAILED
ANALYSIS.
BUT THAT WOULD MEAN A
SIGNIFICANT COURSE CHANGE.
WELL, MR. KIM
IF THERE'S EVEN THE POSSIBILITY
OF FINDING A WORMHOLE
I THINK WE CAN AFFORD A DETOUR.
LIEUTENANT...
INPUT THE COORDINATES
AND CHANGE COURSE.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
AND MAY I SUGGEST
IF THIS WORKS
WE PETITION THE FEDERATION
ASTRONOMICAL COMMITTEE
TO OFFICIALLY DESIGNATE THIS
"THE HARRY KIM WORMHOLE."
CAPTAIN, WE'RE APPROACHING
THE COORDINATES OF THE WORMHOLE.
Janeway:
ON SCREEN.
ARE WE
IN VISUAL RANGE?
AFFIRMATIVE, CAPTAIN,
AND THE ANOMALY
IS STILL REGISTERING
ON SUBSPACE BANDS.
SENSORS ALSO INDICATE
IT'S THERE.
MAGNIFY.
INCREASE TO HIGHEST
MAGNIFICATION.
IF THAT'S A WORMHOLE,
IT MUST BE
THE SMALLEST ONE
ON RECORD.
MR. KIM,
ARE YOU ABLE TO ANALYZE IT?
AYE, CAPTAIN. IT'S
VIRTUALLY MICROSCOPIC.
THE APERTURE IS ONLY ABOUT
30 CENTIMETERS IN DIAMETER.
I GUESS IT'S A LITTLE TOO SMALL
FOR US TO FLY THROUGH.
HOWEVER... IT MIGHT
BE LARGE ENOUGH
TO ACT AS A CONDUIT
FOR A MESSAGE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT COULD CARRY
A COMPRESSED DATA TRANSMISSION
TO FEDERATION SPACE IN MINUTES.
WE STILL HAVE TO FIND OUT
IF IT GOES ANYWHERE
NEAR THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
CAN YOU TRACE
ITS SUBSPACE BEARING?
I CAN'T GET ANY
DIRECTIONAL READINGS AT ALL.
THE APERTURE
IS TOO SMALL.
I RECOMMEND
WE LAUNCH A MICRO-PROBE
INTO THE WORMHOLE.
AGREED. DO IT, LIEUTENANT.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE RECEIVING
TELEMETRY.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE ANY WORMHOLE
I'VE EVER STUDIED.
MICROSCOPIC GRAVITATIONAL EDDIES
EXTREMELY CONSTRICTED
SPATIAL DIMENSIONS...
THE PATHWAY IS BARELY WIDER
THAN THE PROBE ITSELF.
I THINK WHAT WE'RE SEEING
IS A WORMHOLE
IN AN ADVANCED STATE OF DECAY.
MUST BE ANCIENT.
PROBABLY BEEN COLLAPSING
FOR CENTURIES.
DOES THAT MEAN WE CAN'T SEND
A MESSAGE THROUGH IT?
NO. I CAN DO IT.
MAYBE IT'LL TAKE LONGER
TO GET THROUGH
BUT THE WORMHOLE'S
STILL STABLE ENOUGH
TO CARRY A TRANSMISSION.
ANY IDEA YET WHERE THAT MESSAGE
WOULD END UP, ENSIGN?
I'LL TRY EXTRAPOLATING
THE VERTERON EXIT VECTOR.
NO, I CAN'T GET IT.
THERE'S A STRANGE
PHASE VARIANCE
IN THE RADIATION STREAM.
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL THE PROBE EXITS.
THAT SHOULDN'T TAKE LONG.
CAPTAIN, I'M GETTING A
DISTORTED ENERGY READING.
THE PROBE'S TELEMETRY
HAS CHANGED.
IT'S STUCK.
STUCK?
IT'S MIRED IN A
GRAVITATIONAL EDDY
AND BECAUSE THE WORMHOLE'S
IN A STATE OF COLLAPSE,
THOSE EDDIES ARE
INCREDIBLY DENSE.
THAT PROBE
WILL NEVER BREAK FREE, CAPTAIN,
AND WE HAVE NO WAY OF FINDING
OUT WHERE THE WORMHOLE ENDS.
LET'S GIVE IT SOME TIME.
MAYBE IT WILL WORK ITSELF LOOSE.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT, ENSIGN?
OUR PROBE WAS JUST SCANNED.
THERE'S...
THERE'S SOMEBODY ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE WORMHOLE.
IT STARTED ACTING UP
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO.
I'VE BEEN WORKING OUT
IN THE GYM.
MAYBE I OVERDID IT.
IS IT SORE HERE?
YES.
LOCALIZED TENDERNESS
TO THE ULNAR BONE,
NO EPIDERMAL DAMAGE,
MODERATE EDEMA.
WHAT ARE
THE POSSIBLE DIAGNOSES?
EPICONDYLITIS,
STRAINED LIGAMENT,
TORN MUSCLE,
AND HAIRLINE FRACTURE.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
I'VE STUDIED ALL
THE MATERIAL YOU GAVE ME.
I'M READY FOR MORE.
GOOD.
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL MORE
FOR YOU TO LEARN.
THE TRICORDER INDICATES
THIS IS A SMALL STRESS FRACTURE.
CAN THIS GUY DO EVERYTHING
A REAL DOCTOR DOES?
YES, HE CAN.
ACTIVATE IT,
AND DIRECT THE BEAM HERE.
THAT'S IT.
NOT QUITE SO FAST.
IF I HAD TO GET TREATMENT
FOR SOMETHING SERIOUS--
IF I NEEDED SURGERY,
FOR INSTANCE--
WOULD HE BE PERFORMING IT?
OF COURSE,
AND QUITE EXPERTLY TOO.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'D HAVE TO THINK TWICE
ABOUT THAT.
FINE. AND IF YOU
WERE LUCKY,
YOU WOULDN'T DIE
ON THE TABLE
WHILE YOU WERE
MAKING UP YOUR MIND.
THAT SHOULD DO IT.
HOW DOES IT FEEL?
NOT BAD.
THANKS.
DOCTOR, DID
YOU NOTICE
HOW RUDELY THAT
OFFICER TREATED YOU?
NO MORE SO THAN MOST.
YOU MEAN OTHERS
ACT THAT WAY TOO?
LET'S JUST SAY
I'VE BECOME ACCUSTOMED
TO BEING TREATED
LIKE A HYPOSPRAY.
NOW, HERE'S SOME MATERIAL
ON FIRST AID FOR BURNS.
DOCTOR, I THINK I'D LIKE TO DO
MORE THAN STUDY FIRST AID.
I'D BE INTERESTED
IN KNOWING MORE
ABOUT ANATOMY AND PHYSIOLOGY.
YOU'RE INTELLECTUALLY CURIOUS.
I LIKE THAT.
THESE DEAL WITH HUMAN ANATOMY
AND PHYSIOLOGY
BUT THEY WEREN'T WRITTEN
FOR THE LAYMAN.
THEY'RE QUITE TECHNICAL.
I UNDERSTAND.
I'LL DO MY BEST.
AND I REALLY
APPRECIATE YOUR HELP.
WE'VE ANALYZED THE DATA.
SO FAR, OUR SENSORS
HAVE DETECTED
FOUR SEPARATE SCANS
OF THE MICROPROBE--
EACH ONE ON
A PROGRESSIVELY NARROWER BAND.
SOMEONE ON THE OTHER END
OF THAT WORMHOLE
IS DEFINITELY INTERESTED
IN THAT PROBE.
WE CANNOT PRECLUDE
THE POSSIBILITY
THAT THERE IS
A MICROSCOPIC ENTITY
WITHIN THE WORMHOLE
CURIOUS ABOUT AN INTRUDER.
THAT'S POSSIBLE,
BUT YOU'D THINK
OUR PROBE
WOULD HAVE DETECTED
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
WHAT'S THE CONDITION
OF THE PROBE NOW?
I'VE BEEN MONITORING IT
FROM ENGINEERING.
IT'S STILL IMBEDDED IN
THE GRAVITATIONAL EDDY
BUT WITHIN 72 HOURS,
IT WILL BE CRUSHED.
BUT UNTIL THEN,
IT SHOULD CONTINUE
TO TRANSMIT TELEMETRY.
IF WE'RE READING SCANS
FROM THE OTHER SIDE,
IT'S POSSIBLE THE PROBE
IS ACTING AS A RELAY.
IF THAT'S TRUE,
WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO USE IT
TO TRANSMIT A MESSAGE
TO WHOEVER IS EXECUTING
THE SCAN.
YES. I CAN MODIFY OUR
SUBSPACE COMMUNICATIONS BAND
TO ACCEPT THE PROBE
AS A BOOSTER.
LET'S TRY IT, MR. KIM.
I'LL GIVE YOU A HAND.
I FEAR MR. KIM'S EXUBERANCE
MAY TURN INTO AN EQUALLY
INTENSE DISAPPOINTMENT
IF HIS EFFORTS
PROVE IN VAIN.
YOU MAY BE RIGHT,
BUT I'D RATHER ASSUME
THAT HE'S GOING
TO BE SUCCESSFUL.
OKAY, I'VE BOOSTED POWER
TO THE COMMUNICATIONS BANDWIDTH.
NOW, ALL WE HAVE TO DO
IS RECONFIGURE
THE SIGNAL GENERATOR
SO IT'S COMPATIBLE WITH
THE PROBE'S LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
I'M ON IT.
JUST A FEW MINUTES MORE.
THIS HAS TO WORK.
IT'LL MEAN SO MUCH
TO PEOPLE BACK HOME
TO KNOW WE'RE ALIVE
AND HEADED FOR FEDERATION SPACE.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN
GONE THAT LONG.
PEOPLE WON'T GIVE
UP ON US SO SOON.
THEY PROBABLY JUST
THINK WE'RE LOST.
IT'S STILL GOING
TO BE HARD ON MY FOLKS.
I ALWAYS CALLED THEM
ONCE A WEEK
EVEN WHEN I WAS ON
MY TRAINING MISSIONS.
I'VE NEVER BEEN OUT OF CONTACT
FOR SO LONG.
WELL, IT IS GOING
TO WORK, STARFLEET
SO PRETTY SOON THEY'RE GOING
TO KNOW YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
ANY FAMILY?
I HAVEN'T SEEN MY FATHER
SINCE I WAS 5.
HE AND MY MOTHER
SEPARATED.
HE WENT BACK TO EARTH,
AND THAT WAS THE LAST
I SAW OF HIM.
AND YOUR MOM?
I THINK SHE'S ON
THE KLINGON HOME WORLD.
YOU THINK?
WE DIDN'T GET ALONG VERY WELL.
OKAY.
THE SIGNAL GENERATOR
SHOULD BE TUNED
TO THE PROBE'S
LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
ISN'T THERE ANYONE BACK HOME
WHO'D BE WORRIED ABOUT YOU?
THE MAQUIS
ARE AS CLOSE A FAMILY
AS I'VE EVER HAD.
MOST OF MY FRIENDS
ARE HERE ON THE SHIP
SO... NO.
THERE'S NO ONE BACK HOME
WHO'S GOING TO CARE
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER
WHETHER I'M ALIVE.
WE'RE READY TO TRANSMIT.
ENGINEERING TO BRIDGE.
JANEWAY HERE.
We have a communications link
with the micro-probe.
We're going to try sending
a preliminary test signal--
a series
of sub-harmonic pulses.
THEY STAND THE BEST CHANCE
OF TRANSMISSION
THROUGH THE WORMHOLE.
Acknowledged.
PROCEED.
Aye, Captain.
Chakotay:
I'M READING TRANSMISSION
OF THE TEST SIGNAL.
THE PROBE HAS RECEIVED IT
AND RELAYED IT.
HOW WILL WE KNOW
IF THE SIGNAL REACHES SOMEBODY?
THE ONLY WAY...
IS IF THAT SOMEBODY ANSWERS.
THERE'S NO RESPONSE.
IT'S TOO SOON.
REMEMBER, WE HAVE NO IDEA
HOW LONG IT TAKES TO
REACH THE OTHER SIDE.
ARE YOU READING ANYTHING,
MR. TUVOK?
NEGATIVE, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S NOTHING THAT WOULD
SUGGEST A RESPONSE.
EVEN IF SOMEONE
RECEIVES OUR SIGNAL
IT MIGHT TAKE THEM SOME TIME
TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO RETURN IT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
JANEWAY TO KIM.
CONTINUE TRANSMITTING.
Aye, Captain.
HOW LONG
SHOULD WE KEEP IT UP?
Until I tell you otherwise.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE, COMMANDER.
CAPTAIN.
MR. TUVOK.
I'M GETTING SOMETHING, CAPTAIN.
I'M GETTING IT, TOO.
A SUBSPACE SIGNAL
RELAYED THROUGH THE PROBE.
THAT SIGNAL'S
BEING TRANSMITTED
EXACTLY THE SAME
FREQUENCY AND AMPLITUDE
AS OUR SIGNAL.
IT'S A RESPONSE.
SOMEONE RECEIVED
OUR TRANSMISSION
AND SENT ONE BACK,
AND THEIR SIGNAL
ORIGINATED IN THE...
ALPHA QUADRANT.
CAPTAIN'S LOG--SUPPLEMENTAL.
ENCOURAGED BY HIS SUCCESS
IN TRANSMITTING A SIGNAL
TO THE ALPHA QUADRANT,
MR. KIM IS INVESTIGATING
THE POSSIBILITY
OF ESTABLISHING A VOICE LINK
WITH WHOEVER IS AT
THE OTHER END OF THE WORMHOLE.
( door chimes )
COME IN.
KES, THIS IS A SURPRISE.
AM I INTERRUPTING?
NOT AT ALL.
I WAS JUST GOING TO HAVE
A CUP OF SOUP.
WOULD YOU LIKE ANYTHING?
SPINACH JUICE
WITH A TOUCH OF PEAR, PLEASE.
TOM PARIS INTRODUCED ME TO IT.
IT'S VERY NUTRITIOUS.
I'M SURE.
COMPUTER, ONE SPINACH JUICE
WITH A TOUCH OF PEAR
AND ONE CUP
OF VEGETABLE BOUILLON.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
IF THERE WERE
A MEMBER OF THE CREW
WHOSE NEEDS
WEREN'T BEING MET
WOULD YOU WANT
TO KNOW ABOUT IT?
OF COURSE.
KES, DO YOU
AND NEELIX FEEL
THAT YOUR NEEDS
ARE BEING IGNORED?
OF COURSE NOT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY HERE.
I'M REFERRING
TO THE DOCTOR.
THE DOCTOR.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY PEOPLE TREAT HIM
THE WAY THEY DO.
HOW DO PEOPLE
TREAT HIM?
AS THOUGH
HE DOESN'T EXIST.
THEY TALK ABOUT HIM
WHILE HE'S STANDING RIGHT THERE.
THEY IGNORE HIM,
THEY INSULT HIM.
WELL, AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I'VE BEEN HEARING
THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE COIN.
MANY OF THE CREW HAVE COMPLAINED
THAT THE DOCTOR
IS BRUSQUE, EVEN RUDE.
THAT HE LACKS
ANY BEDSIDE MANNER.
WE'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
REPROGRAMMING HIM.
YOU CAN DO THAT?
IT DOESN'T SEEM RIGHT.
KES, HE'S ONLY
A HOLOGRAM.
HE'S YOUR MEDICAL OFFICER.
HE'S ALIVE.
NO, HE'S NOT.
HE'S SELF-AWARE.
HE'S COMMUNICATIVE.
HE HAS THE ABILITY TO LEARN.
BECAUSE HE'S BEEN PROGRAMMED
TO DO THAT.
SO BECAUSE HE'S A HOLOGRAM,
HE DOESN'T HAVE TO BE TREATED
WITH RESPECT
OR ANY CONSIDERATION
AT ALL?
VERY WELL.
I'LL LOOK INTO IT.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
OKAY, WE'LL BE READY TO GO
ONLINE IN A COUPLE MINUTES.
I'M STILL WORRIED ABOUT THE
GRAVITATIONAL INTERFERENCE.
I DON'T THINK THE
COVARIANT ISOLATOR
WILL BE EFFECTIVE WITH
A VOCAL TRANSMISSION.
LET'S TRY INVERTING
THE NARROW BAND FILTER.
PROGRESS REPORT,
ENSIGN.
I THINK WE'RE READY TO
GIVE IT A TRY.
BUT WE'RE PUSHING THROUGH
SOME PRETTY HEAVY
GRAVITATIONAL INTERFERENCE.
I CAN'T GUARANTEE THE CLARITY
OF THE TRANSMISSION.
LET'S SEE
WHAT HAPPENS.
THIS IS CAPTAIN KATHRYN JANEWAY
OF THE FEDERATION STARSHIP
VOYAGER.
DO YOU READ?
( static )
I'LL NARROW THE FILTER BAND-PASS
SOME MORE.
TRY AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS KATHRYN JANEWAY
OF THE FEDERATION SHIP VOYAGER.
IS ANYONE RECEIVING
THIS COMMUNICATION?
( static )
...vessel...
NARROW THE BAND-PASS
A LITTLE MORE.
TRY AGAIN, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS JANEWAY.
PLEASE REPEAT
YOUR LAST TRANSMISSION.
( static )
...of the cargo vessel...
...Quadrant...
...your location.
CARGO VESSEL,
WE'RE STILL TRYING
TO CLEAR UP
YOUR LAST TRANSMISSION.
PLEASE REPEAT
ONE MORE TIME.
The captain
of the cargo vessel Talvath.
Location Alpha Quadrant,
Sector 1385.
What is your location?
WE ARE IN THE DELTA QUADRANT,
BUT SINCE THIS QUADRANT
HASN'T BEEN CHARTED,
I CAN'T SPECIFY
OUR EXACT LOCATION.
Please confirm.
You said Delta Quadrant?
CORRECT.
In a Federation starship?
YES. WE WERE ON A MISSION,
AND WE GOT PULLED
INTO THIS QUADRANT.
Pulled in? How?
IT'S A COMPLICATED STORY.
PLEASE, IF YOU WOULD JUST
TRY DECONSTRUCTING
THE PHASE SHIFT OF
OUR HAILING FREQUENCY
YOU COULD VERIFY.
You are undoubtedly
still in the Alpha Quadrant.
What are your coordinates?
I ASSURE YOU
I AM TELLING YOU THE TRUTH.
WE ARE IN THE DELTA QUADRANT,
70,000 LIGHT YEARS FROM YOU.
This is preposterous.
You are obviously lying.
I am terminating
the communication.
NO. NO, WAIT.
KIM, HAIL HIM AGAIN.
NO RESPONSE, CAPTAIN.
WHY WOULD HE HAVE BROKEN OFF
TRANSMISSION?
PERHAPS I CAN OFFER
AN EXPLANATION.
THE COMLINK SIGNATURE
OF HIS TRANSMISSION INDICATES
THE MESSAGE ORIGINATED
FROM A ROMULAN SHIP.
FURTHER, THERE ARE NO
KNOWN SHIPPING LANES
IN THE SECTOR HE IDENTIFIED.
GIVEN THE PRECISE CALIBRATION
OF HIS SIGNAL, I WOULD SUGGEST
THAT HE IS IN FACT
ONBOARD A SCIENCE VESSEL.
WHY WOULD HE PRETEND
TO BE A CARGO CAPTAIN?
IF HE'S ENGAGED IN SOME KIND
OF SECRET RESEARCH
HE MIGHT WANT
TO CONCEAL THAT FACT.
PRECISELY, WHEN WE CLAIMED
TO BE TRANSMITTING
FROM THE DELTA QUADRANT--
AN IMPOSSIBILITY
SO FAR AS HE KNOWS--
HE MAY HAVE FEARED
WE WERE FEDERATION SPIES.
JUST OUR LUCK. WE RAISE ONE SHIP
FROM THE ALPHA QUADRANT
AND IT HAS
TO BE ROMULAN.
THAT ROMULAN
STILL HAS THE ABILITY
TO GET A MESSAGE TO STARFLEET.
MR. KIM
HAIL THE TALVATH
REPEATEDLY.
CALL ME THE MINUTE
YOU RE-ESTABLISH CONTACT.
COMMANDER, YOU HAVE
THE BRIDGE.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
COMPUTER, INITIATE EMERGENCY
MEDICAL HOLOGRAPHIC PROGRAM.
PLEASE STATE THE NATURE OF
THE MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
THERE IS NO EMERGENCY,
DOCTOR.
WELL... THAT'S GOOD.
I WAS RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF PREPARING A CULTURE
TO TEST LIEUTENANT HARGROVE
FOR ARETHEAN FLU WHEN
ENSIGN KYOTO DEACTIVATED ME.
I'M SURE SHE DIDN'T REALIZE
YOU WERE BUSY.
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT,
CAPTAIN?
ACTUALLY, I THOUGHT
WE MIGHT JUST...
TALK FOR A MOMENT.
ABOUT WHAT?
DOCTOR, YOU WERE ORIGINALLY
PROGRAMMED TO SERVE
IN A LIMITED FASHION
DURING AN EMERGENCY.
NOW YOU'RE BEING ASKED
TO DO MUCH MORE.
THAT'S CERTAINLY TRUE.
I'M PROVIDING FULL-TIME
MEDICAL SERVICE
FOR THE ENTIRE SHIP'S CREW
FUNCTIONING AS BOTH
DOCTOR AND NURSE
AND NOW AS AN
INSTRUCTOR AS WELL.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY
OF THINKING OF YOURSELF
AS AN EMERGENCY
MEDICAL PROGRAM ANYMORE.
YOU'VE BECOME A FULL-FLEDGED
MEMBER OF THE CREW.
I SEE.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING
THAT I BE REPROGRAMMED?
NO.
I'M ASKING IF THERE'S
ANYTHING I CAN DO...
TO HELP YOU.
HELP ME?
IF THERE'S ANYTHING
YOU NEED OR WANT
I'D LIKE TO SEE
THAT YOU GET IT.
WHAT I'D LIKE IS TO BE TURNED
OFF WHEN PEOPLE LEAVE.
I SPEND HOURS HERE
WITH ABSOLUTELY NOTHING TO DO.
WHEN SOMEONE DOES REMEMBER
TO DEACTIVATE ME,
THEY DO SO WITHOUT ASKING
IF IT'S CONVENIENT.
IT'S EXTREMELY IRRITATING.
WHAT IF I GAVE YOU CONTROL...
OVER YOUR
DEACTIVATION SEQUENCE?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
I'M SURE
WE CAN MAKE IT POSSIBLE
FOR YOU
TO TURN YOURSELF OFF
OR TO PREVENT
BEING TURNED OFF.
I... I MIGHT LIKE THAT.
I'LL HAVE SOMEONE
LOOK INTO IT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
I'M NOT SURE.
I'LL HAVE TO GIVE IT
SOME THOUGHT.
YOU DO THAT.
Kim to Captain Janeway.
JANEWAY HERE.
Captain, we've got him back--
the Romulan.
GOOD WORK.
PUT HIM THROUGH TO MY QUARTERS.
THIS IS KATHRYN JANEWAY.
This is the cargo vessel
Talvath.
THANK YOU FOR ANSWERING
OUR HAIL, CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
HOW MAY I ADDRESS YOU?
I'd prefer not to give my name.
VERY WELL.
I UNDERSTAND THAT
YOU MUST HAVE BEEN SKEPTICAL
WHEN I TOLD YOU WHERE WE ARE.
I HOPE YOU'VE BEEN ABLE
TO VERIFY OUR POSITION.
My analysis of your hailing
frequency seems to indicate
that it originates
in the Delta Quadrant,
but I am not precluding
the possibility
that you've been able to create
that illusion somehow.
TO WHAT END?
I'm not sure, but that doesn't
negate the possibility.
HOW CAN I ASSURE YOU
OF MY TRUTHFULNESS?
You say
you're a Federation ship.
Are you a Starfleet vessel?
YES, WE ARE.
And your mission
in the Delta Quadrant?
OUR MISSION WAS ORIGINALLY
IN THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
WE WERE PULLED AGAINST OUR WILL
TO OUR PRESENT LOCATION.
NOW WE'RE TRYING TO GET HOME.
Aren't you in fact
Starfleet spies
on a surveillance mission?
CAPTAIN, I UNDERSTAND
YOUR CONCERN.
NATURALLY, THE ROMULAN EMPIRE
DOESN'T WANT STARFLEET
SPYING ON ITS SCIENCE VESSELS
BUT SINCE WE'RE 70,000
LIGHT YEARS FROM ROMULAN SPACE
AND A SUBSPACE MESSAGE
TO STARFLEET WOULD TAKE YEARS
I THINK YOU HAVE TO ADMIT
THAT WE CAN'T BE MUCH
OF A THREAT TO YOU.
YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO FEAR FROM US.
Soothing words, Captain,
but they are only words.
IF WE WERE SPIES...
WE WOULDN'T BE ASKING
WHAT I'M GOING TO ASK YOU NOW.
WE HAVE NO WAY OF COMMUNICATING
WITH STARFLEET...
WITH OUR FRIENDS AND FAMILIES.
WE'RE HOPING YOU MIGHT BE ABLE
TO RELAY A MESSAGE FOR US.
OUR CREW IS NOT LARGE.
EACH OF THEM COULD WRITE
A SHORT, PERSONAL MESSAGE.
YOU'D BE WELCOME TO READ
THEM ALL BEFORE PASSING THEM ON.
AND I THINK YOU'D BE CONVINCED
THAT THEY'RE NOTHING MORE
THAN THE HEARTFELT WORDS
OF SOME...
VERY LONELY PEOPLE.
Captain...
it would ease my apprehension
if I could see that you are
who you say you are.
I have a signal amplifier
on board.
I've been working
to reconfigure the protocols
to penetrate the radiation
stream of the wormhole.
I think it might be possible
to establish
a visual link between us.
I HAVE NO OBJECTION.
WHEN THAT'S DONE...
WILL YOU HELP US?
I make no promises.
Let us proceed
one step at a time.
Have your officers contact me
in order to attempt
the visual link.
Good night.
GOOD NIGHT.
WE'RE READY TO TRY A VISUAL LINK
WITH THE ROMULAN SHIP, CAPTAIN.
GOOD WORK.
WE DIDN'T HAVE ANY TROUBLE
CONFIGURING THE PROTOCOLS.
BUT THAT PHASE VARIANCE
IN THE RADIATION STREAM
GAVE US A FEW PROBLEMS.
TORRES IS GOING TO BALANCE IT
MANUALLY FROM ENGINEERING.
OKAY, WE'VE GOT
THE COMMUNICATIONS
FREQUENCY LOCKED IN.
ON SCREEN.
I presume you are
Captain Janeway.
YES.
I WANT
TO THANK YOU, CAPTAIN,
FOR MAINTAINING CONTACT
WITH US.
IT MEANS A GREAT DEAL
TO ME AND TO MY CREW.
I am not familiar
with this class of ship.
IT'S NEW,
BUT IT ISN'T CLASSIFIED.
I'M A LITTLE SURPRISED
YOUR INTELLIGENCE
HASN'T PROVIDED YOU
WITH INFORMATION.
I've been at space
for over a year, Captain,
and am not privy
to the latest intelligence.
I'm sure that our operatives
have provided the government
with the detailed information
about your new ship.
NO DOUBT.
CAPTAIN, HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE
TO COMMUNICATE
WITH YOUR GOVERNMENT
ABOUT SENDING
OUR MESSAGES?
I have.
They've promised to take
the matter under advisement.
I SEE.
AND WHEN DO YOU THINK
THEY WILL HAVE AN ANSWER?
It is impossible
to predict the timetable
of the Romulan Senate.
When they've made
their decision,
I will hear from them.
WE DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY
OF A GREAT DEAL OF TIME.
MY OFFICERS ARE PREDICTING THAT
THE PROBE WILL BECOME INOPERABLE
IN THE NEXT 48 HOURS.
Captain, I am
a low-ranking scientist
a minor functionary.
It is not my place
to tell the Romulan Senate
to speed up their
decision-making process.
YOU SAID YOU'VE BEEN IN SPACE
FOR OVER A YEAR.
DO YOU HAVE ANY FAMILY?
Yes.
I ASSUME THEY'RE NOT
WITH YOU IN SPACE.
My wife... and my daughter
are on Romulus.
A DAUGHTER.
HOW OLD IS SHE?
She is... seven months.
THEN YOU'VE NEVER SEEN HER.
To my sorrow, no.
She will be two years old
before I get back.
YOU MUST MISS YOUR FAMILY
VERY MUCH.
I knew when I accepted
this assignment
that there would be
a price to pay.
Perhaps I didn't realize
how high that price would be.
CAPTAIN...
EVERY ONE OF US ON THIS SHIP
HAS LEFT BEHIND FRIENDS, FAMILY
LOVED ONES.
WE MAY NOT SEE THEM AGAIN
FOR YEARS...
MAYBE NEVER.
SO WE CAN ALL UNDERSTAND
HOW LONELY YOU MUST BE.
SURELY YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
OUR FEELINGS AS WELL.
WE WOULD BE DEEPLY GRATEFUL
FOR ANY EFFORTS YOU MIGHT MAKE
TO PERSUADE YOUR GOVERNMENT
TO SEND OUR MESSAGES.
I cannot guarantee success,
but I will try to persuade
my superiors to make
their decision quickly...
and positively.
THANK YOU.
I will contact you again.
COMMANDER, LET'S
ASSUME HE'S GOING
TO BE SUCCESSFUL.
TELL THE CREW
TO PREPARE PERSONAL MESSAGES
AND HAVE THEM READY
WITHIN THE HOUR.
WITH PLEASURE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN, I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU.
GO AHEAD, TORRES.
NO! I MEAN, IN PRIVATE.
I THINK THIS WILL WORK,
CAPTAIN,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT TO BRING IT UP
IN FRONT OF THE CREW.
IT WOULDN'T BE RIGHT
TO GET THEIR HOPES UP
IN CASE IT DOESN'T WORK.
ALTHOUGH, I THINK IT WILL.
SLOW DOWN, TORRES.
AND TELL ME WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THE PHASE AMPLITUDE
OF THE VISUAL LINK
WITH THE ROMULAN SHIP--
IT'S WITHIN
JUST A FEW MEGAHERTZ
OF MEETING
TRANSPORTER PROTOCOLS.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING..?
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO PIGGY-BACK
A TRANSPORTER BEAM
ONTO THE VISUAL LINK.
WE COULD TRANSPORT THE ENTIRE
CREW BACK TO THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
YOU'LL HAVE TO RECONFIGURE
THE MATTER TRANSMISSION RATE
FAIRLY SUBSTANTIALLY.
AND WE RISK LOSING
WHATEVER WE TRY TO BEAM OUT.
WE'LL HAVE TO RUN
A SERIES OF TESTS FIRST.
SEE TO IT, LIEUTENANT.
I'LL NEED SOME HELP.
YOU HAVE MY AUTHORIZATION
TO USE ANY OF THE SHIP'S
PERSONNEL YOU NEED.
THIS IS TOP PRIORITY.
AND DON'T WORRY ABOUT SECRECY.
I DOUBT YOU'LL BE ABLE TO
KEEP THIS QUIET FOR VERY LONG.
I FINISHED THESE,
AND I'M READY FOR MORE.
YOU FINISHED THOSE ALREADY?
I ENJOYED STUDYING ANATOMY.
IT WOULD BE INTERESTING
TO SEE AN AUTOPSY SOMETIME.
WHAT ARE THE BONES
OF THE MIDDLE EAR?
MALLEUS, INCUS AND STAPES.
AND THE CONNECTIVE TISSUE
BETWEEN THE MIDDLE
AND THE EXTERNAL
AUDITORY CANAL?
THE TYMPANIC MEMBRANE.
HMM, I SUSPECT YOU HAVE
AN EIDETIC MEMORY--
AN ASTONISHING GIFT.
I'LL DO A FULL NEURAL SCAN
ON YOU AT SOME POINT.
I'VE BEEN THINKING...
IF WE DO GET BACK
TO FEDERATION SPACE
I'D LIKE TO EXPLORE
THE POSSIBILITY
OF GOING TO MEDICAL SCHOOL.
IF YOU CONTINUE TO APPLY
YOURSELF AS YOU HAVE,
BY THE TIME WE GET BACK,
YOU MAY ALREADY HAVE THE
EQUIVALENT OF A MEDICAL DEGREE.
THEN YOU HAVEN'T HEARD?
HEARD WHAT?
THAT WE MIGHT BE GETTING
BACK SOON.
IF THERE'S ONE THING
YOU CAN COUNT ON
IT'S THAT I AM THE LAST
TO BE TOLD
ABOUT ANYTHING THAT HAPPENS
ON THIS SHIP.
EVERYONE'S TALKING ABOUT IT.
THERE MAY BE A WAY
TO TRANSPORT ALL OF US
TO THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
CHIEF TORRES
AND HALF OF ENGINEERING
ARE WORKING ON IT
RIGHT NOW.
I SEE.
WELL, I'LL SAY GOOD-BYE NOW.
I WON'T BE TRANSPORTING
WITH THE REST OF YOU.
BUT CAN'T WE DOWNLOAD YOUR
PROGRAM AND TAKE YOU WITH US?
MY PROGRAM IS FULLY INTEGRATED
INTO THE SICK BAY SYSTEM.
AT PRESENT,
I CANNOT BE DOWNLOADED.
THANK YOU
FOR EVERYTHING.
WAIT. I'D LIKE...
THAT IS..
COULD I ASK A FAVOR OF YOU?
ANYTHING.
IF YOU DO LEAVE,
BEFORE YOU GO
WOULD YOU CHECK TO MAKE SURE
I'VE BEEN DEACTIVATED?
I PROMISE.
OUR CHIEF ENGINEER HAS MANAGED
TO BIND A TRANSPORTER BEAM
TO THE VISUAL LINK
BETWEEN US.
Then you've matched
your data transmission
to the phase amplitude
of our com signal?
EXACTLY.
Apparently
our intelligence operatives
are not doing their job.
You clearly have technology
that we are unaware of.
This would be
an incredible breakthrough
in subspace field mechanics.
IF IT'S SUCCESSFUL,
WE'D LIKE TO TRY TRANSMITTING
A TEST CYLINDER TO YOU.
A test cylinder of what sort?
IT IS A STANDARD
STARFLEET MECHANISM
WITH A VARIETAL
MOLECULAR MATRIX.
IT SIMULATES MOST KNOWN ORGANIC
AND NON-ORGANIC COMPOUNDS.
IT IS NOT
CLASSIFIED TECHNOLOGY.
Ah, I am aware
of this mechanism.
We use a similar device.
I will allow the transport.
Janeway:
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM 1.
Torres here.
WE'RE ALL SET, CAPTAIN.
THE LOCK IS ACTIVE
AND WE'RE FOCUSED
ON THE ROMULANS'
transporter coordinates.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
LET'S GIVE IT A TRY.
ENERGIZE.
THE CYLINDER HAS
DEMATERIALIZED, CAPTAIN.
CAN YOU GET IT BACK?
The pattern buffer
IS HAVING TROUBLE ACCEPTING
THE MATTER STREAM.
I'll increase power to the phase
transmission coils.
RAMP THE COILS
TO 37 MEGAJOULES.
37 MEGAJOULES.
Congratulations, Captain.
You've done it.
Very impressive.
WE SHOULD RUN A SERIES OF
THESE TESTS JUST TO MAKE SURE.
BUT WE HAVE TO ACT QUICKLY
BEFORE THE PROBE IS CRUSHED.
I understand.
EVENTUALLY WE'LL HAVE TO TRY
TRANSPORTING A PERSON.
ONE OF OUR CREW
WILL BEAM TO YOUR SHIP
IF YOU'LL ALLOW IT.
I'm afraid
I can't permit that, Captain.
My government would never allow
Starfleet personnel
on this ship.
I wouldn't want my logs
to show that activity.
THEN WHAT WOULD YOU SUGGEST?
I'll volunteer to transport
to your ship... and back again.
BUT, CAPTAIN, IF WE CAN'T
TRANSPORT TO YOUR SHIP,
HOW ARE WE TO GET BACK?
If the procedure is successful
I'll arrange for a troop ship
to join me.
That would easily accommodate
your crew.
VERY WELL.
WE'LL BE IN TOUCH.
KIM AND TORRES HAVE MADE
MORE THAN 20 TRANSPORTS
OF THE TEST CYLINDER.
EVEN THOUGH SHE'S STILL
HAVING TROUBLE
WITH THAT PHASE VARIANCE,
EVERY ONE OF THEM HAS
BEEN SUCCESSFUL.
LET'S HOPE IT GOES AS WELL
WITH THE ROMULAN.
CAPTAIN, I MUST INSIST I STAY
WITH HIM AT ALL TIMES.
WHILE HE'S ONBOARD.
AGREED.
WE'RE LOCKED ON TO HIM.
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY, CAPTAIN.
WELL, LET'S TRY IT.
ENERGIZE...
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
IT'S THE PHASE VARIANCE
IN THE RADIATION STREAM.
I'M BALANCING IT MANUALLY.
WELCOME TO THE DELTA QUADRANT...
CAPTAIN.
MY FIRST OFFICER,
COMMANDER CHAKOTAY
LIEUTENANT TUVOK,
HEAD OF SECURITY
CHIEF ENGINEER TORRES...
AND OPERATIONS OFFICER KIM.
MY CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR
REMARKABLE ACCOMPLISHMENT.
THIS IS AN ASTONISHING
BREAKTHROUGH.
FOR A WHILE THERE I DIDN'T
THINK YOU WERE GOING TO MAKE IT.
THERE WAS A STRANGE
PHASE VARIANCE
IN THE RADIATION STREAM.
IT ALMOST KEPT US
FROM PULLING YOU THROUGH.
MR. TUVOK, YOU MAY BEGIN
EVACUATION PROCEDURES.
I SUGGEST WE DELAY THAT
FOR THE MOMENT, CAPTAIN.
I'M AFRAID I FOUND THE REASON
FOR THE UNUSUAL PHASE VARIANCE.
WHAT IS IT?
CAPTAIN, WHAT YEAR IS IT?
WHAT YEAR?
IF YOU PLEASE.
BY YOUR CALENDAR,
THE YEAR IS 2351.
BUT... THIS IS 2371.
EXACTLY. OUR ROMULAN VISITOR
IS A PERSON OUT OF TIME.
HE'S SHOWING CLEAR EVIDENCE
OF TEMPORAL DISPLACEMENT.
I WOULD SURMISE
THAT THE WORMHOLE IS A RIFT,
NOT JUST IN SPACE,
BUT IN TIME.
THE UNUSUAL PHASE VARIANCE
WE DETECTED
WAS ACTUALLY AN INDICATION
OF A TEMPORAL SHIFT.
WE HAVE TRANSPORTED HIM
FROM 20 YEARS IN THE PAST
TO OUR PRESENT.
I'VE GONE OVER AND OVER
THE TRANSPORTER LOGS.
THERE IS NO QUESTION THAT
IF WE TRY TO TRANSPORT OURSELVES
THROUGH THAT WORMHOLE
WE'LL END UP 20 YEARS
IN THE PAST.
THEN LET'S DO IT.
IT'S BETTER THAN SPENDING
THE NEXT 70 YEARS
TRYING TO GET BACK.
Paris:
HOW CAN WE DO THAT?
WE'D BE GOING BACK TO A TIME
WHEN YOU WERE ONLY 2 YEARS OLD.
I KNOW YOU'RE
DISAPPOINTED, HARRY.
WE ALL ARE.
IT SEEMED WE WERE SO CLOSE...
BUT CLEARLY WE CAN'T GO BACK.
IT WOULD POLLUTE THE TIMELINE
TO SUCH AN EXTENT
THAT THE CONSEQUENCES
WOULD BE UNIMAGINABLE.
I'M AFRAID WE'LL HAVE
TO SEND YOU BACK ALONE
AND ASK THAT YOU
NOT REVEAL ANYTHING
THAT HAS HAPPENED HERE.
I CAN ASSURE YOU, CAPTAIN,
THAT I WOULD NOT DO
ANYTHING THAT MIGHT
CONTAMINATE THE FUTURE
AND PERHAPS HARM
THE ROMULAN EMPIRE.
BUT...
IN 20 YEARS...
I COULD ALERT STARFLEET
NOT TO LAUNCH
THE MISSION
WHICH SENT YOU HERE.
I'M AFRAID
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE EITHER.
WE'VE ALREADY HAD A HUGE IMPACT
ON THIS QUADRANT.
PEOPLE AND EVENTS HERE
WOULD BE DRASTICALLY
AFFECTED.
I'M AFRAID WE'RE LEFT
WITH OUR ORIGINAL REQUEST.
IN 20 YEARS...
WOULD YOU RELAY OUR PERSONAL
MESSAGES TO STARFLEET?
OF COURSE.
AT THE PROPER TIME,
I WILL TRANSMIT THEM.
IF YOU SHOULD FIND A WAY BACK
WITHIN MY LIFETIME...
I'D BE AN OLD MAN
BUT I WOULD WELCOME
A MESSAGE FROM YOU.
I AM TELEK R'MOR OF THE ROMULAN
ASTROPHYSICAL ACADEMY.
I PROMISE YOU'LL HEAR FROM US...
BECAUSE WE WILL GET BACK.
THESE ARE OUR MESSAGES.
I WISH YOU LUCK ON YOUR JOURNEY.
AND I THANK YOU FOR YOUR HELP.
ENERGIZE.
HIS SIGNAL'S
IN THE PATTERN BUFFER.
TRANSFERRING
TO THE EMITTER ARRAY.
PHASE VARIANCE
IS OUT OF SYNC AGAIN.
COMPENSATING.
TRANSPORT COMPLETE, CAPTAIN.
HE MADE IT.
I'LL TELL THE CREW.
THEY CAN HAVE
THE SATISFACTION OF KNOWING
THAT THEIR MESSAGES
HAVE REACHED THEIR FAMILIES.
Tuvok:
CAPTAIN.
I DID NOT WANT TO MENTION THIS
UNTIL AFTER OUR GUEST HAD LEFT.
I CHECKED
THE COMPUTER DATABANKS
FOR A ROMULAN SCIENTIST
NAMED TELEK R'MOR.
AND?
I'M SORRY TO REPORT
DR. R'MOR DIED IN 2367.
( softly ):
THAT WAS FOUR YEARS AGO.
THAT IS CORRECT.
BEFORE HE WOULD HAVE SENT
OUR MESSAGES.
MAYBE HE LEFT A WILL
TELLING SOMEONE ELSE
TO TRANSMIT THE MESSAGES
OR HE COULD HAVE GIVEN
OUR COMPUTER CHIP
TO THE ROMULAN GOVERNMENT.
IT IS POSSIBLE.
UNFORTUNATELY,
THERE IS NO WAY TO KNOW.
THEN LET'S MOVE ON.
WE'VE GOT A LONG WAY TO GO.
I TRIED A NEW
HAMSTRING EXERCISE.
MAYBE I OVERDID IT
BUT MY WORKOUTS ARE ABOUT
ALL THAT STAND BETWEEN ME
AND A SEVERE CASE
OF CABIN FEVER
LIEUTENANT, I AM THE CHIEF
MEDICAL OFFICER OF THIS SHIP.
IF YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO SAY TO ME
PLEASE DIRECT
THE STATEMENT TO ME.
WELL...
YOU SEE, I NEED TO WORK OUT.
I'M NOT TELLING YOU
NOT TO WORK OUT.
I'M SUGGESTING YOU USE A MODICUM
OF COMMON SENSE WHEN YOU DO IT.
IF I SEE YOU IN HERE AGAIN
FOR AN EXERCISE-RELATED INJURY
I'LL HAVE TO DISCUSS THE MATTER
WITH YOUR SUPERIOR OFFICER.
YES... SIR.
YOU'RE FINE NOW.
YOU MAY LEAVE.
YES, SIR.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I DON'T THINK
HE'LL MAKE THE MISTAKE
OF IGNORING YOU AGAIN.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY HAS MADE ME
REALIZE THAT I MUST FUNCTION
AS MORE THAN AN EMERGENCY
MEDICAL REPLACEMENT.
I MUST THINK OF MYSELF
AS A... MEMBER OF THE CREW.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I'VE PREPARED
A LIST OF THINGS
I'D LIKE TO SEE
ADDED TO SICK BAY.
PERHAPS YOU COULD
PRESENT IT TO THE CAPTAIN?
I'D BE HAPPY TO.
THERE'S ONE MORE REQUEST.
SOMETHING OF A...
A PERSONAL NATURE.
I WOULD LIKE...
A NAME.