MALE:
What do you see, Mr. Paris?
PARIS:
Shoes...
muddy shoes.
( whining )
The dog.
Good. That's exactly
what you should see.
But that isn't possible.
I'm sure it's disorienting
to see yourself
through another man's eyes.
No, I...
Tolen!
TOLEN:
Now I understand.
I'd better be
on my way.
You don't have
to go, Tom.
He's got no right.
No right?
This is my home!
You come into my home
and steal my wife,
and I have no right?!
That's not the way
it happened.
This isn't the way it happened!
The trial's over, Mr. Paris.
There's no point
to further denials.
I know about you, Paris.
I know you were in prison.
That has nothing
to do with...
We'll see what your Captain
has to say about this.
When I'm finished
with you,
you'll never wear
that uniform again!
PARIS:
I can't let you do that.
WIFE:
No, Tom! Don't! Stop!
No. I didn't...
( Tolen yelling )
WIFE: Tom, no!
( gagging and gasping )
( Tolen groaning )
Let the record show
that the sentence of the court
has been carried out.
For the rest
of his natural life,
once every 14 hours,
Thomas Eugene Paris
will relive the last moments
of his victim's life.
May the fates have
mercy on you, sir.
If the hydroxyproline level
is elevated this high,
you'd probably call
for a pancreatic scan.
That's exactly
what I'd call for.
All right, then.
Let's run through the
osteographic series again.
Just enter the responses
you're sure about.
So have you given any
more thought to a name?
I asked the Captain
for one.
Why don't you
choose one yourself?
Choose one myself?
Me?
Well, that just isn't...
Holograms are
programmed, Kes.
They don't choose
anything for themselves.
Why not?
Because we're not capable
of choosing.
Well, you choose
what medical treatment
to give someone.
I'm programmed
with over five million
possible treatments,
with contingency programs
and adaptive programs,
but it's all programs
upon programs upon programs.
There's no independent
decision-making.
I don't see
the difference.
The difference is...
I base decisions
on information stored
inside my brain.
How is that so different
from the way you access
your programs?
Well, if you put it
that way...
Do your programs have
any names in them?
Certainly.
I have the names
of Starfleet doctors,
their patients...
medical personnel
in historical
and literary contexts...
So pick a name.
Just... pick one?
Pick a name you like--
perhaps from someone
who inspires you.
Doctor... Dr. Galen.
Dr. Salk. Doctor...
Those are good.
...Spock.
Can you see yourself
with any of those names?
Not exactly.
Take your time.
After all, you
will be that name
for the rest of your life.
Hmm. I never even considered
that I had a life.
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Activate emergency
medical holographic program.
I'm already on, Captain.
What can I do for you?
We've got an incoming shuttle
with an injured crewman
on board.
Any details?
It's either Ensign Kim
or Lieutenant Paris.
We haven't been able
to raise them.
Sensors indicate damage
to various subsystems.
You're sure there's only
one life sign aboard?
That is confirmed,
Captain.
Transport him to Sick Bay.
I'll be down there.
Mr. Tuvok?
They made me leave
without him.
He's severely
dehydrated.
No sleep.
Neodextraline
solution?
Prepare an I.V.
Can you tell us what happened
to Paris, Mr. Kim?
They made me leave
without him.
They said he'd committed
a... a murder.
Do you have any idea
who the victim was?
An engineering physicist
we were working with.
His name was Tolen Ren.
The Banean Minister of Science
introduced us to him
just after we'd arrived.
So from the other
side of the galaxy.
70,000 light-years,
give or take a few.
That's a long trip home
with a damaged collimator.
If anybody on this world can
help you, Professor Ren can.
He's developed
four generations
of navigational arrays
for our ships.
We have to stay one step ahead
of our neighbors, the Numiri.
Did you bring your ship's
specifications with you?
It's all here.
TOLEN: Splendid.
Why don't we begin to look it
over at my home this evening?
My wife would be delighted
to have company for supper.
KIM:
There was no reason to say no,
but if we hadn't
gone with him that night,
none of this would've happened.
( barks )
Oh, come on now, Neeka,
stop that racket.
They're friends!
( chuckling ):
That's better. That's better.
What a good doggie.
Oh, dearest?
Are you dressed?
We have guests.
I should have called.
I just don't think
of the common courtesies.
She's really wonderful
about, uh, tolerating
my dreadful manners.
So you've done it to me again.
Yes, dear.
I apologize.
Lidell, this is
Ensign Harry Kim
and Lieutenant
Tom Paris.
They're from the other
side of the galaxy.
Hello.
Nice to
meet you.
You might have called.
You're absolutely right.
Do you have enough
to feed us all
or shall we go out?
No, it's fine.
I have some leftover
rolk from yesterday.
I'll just throw it
in the stew.
Wonderful! Gentlemen,
make yourselves at home.
I'm going to put on
my slippers.
Lidell will take
good care of you.
Would you like a drink?
Sure.
Help yourself.
What are you
looking at?
Not the same thing
that you're looking at,
that's for sure.
( Neeka barks )
What are you looking at?
( Neeka continues barking )
If it's spoiled,
Neeka wouldn't eat it.
Nothing too fancy
or exotic around here.
We're very simple folks.
You're very kind to include us
at your supper table.
We enjoy
an occasional guest.
I think Lidell
would prefer us
to entertain more often
than we do, yes?
She's, uh, far more social
than I am.
I'm afraid she gets a little
bored here sometimes.
I'm so consumed with my work.
And here we are bringing
more of it home
to take your husband's attention
away for the evening.
Whether you were
here or not
makes no difference.
Tolen would work anyway.
I'm afraid she's right.
We are at war, after all.
By the way, how did you
get past the Numiri patrols?
Lieutenant Paris
is our best pilot.
Captain Janeway decided not
to take our ship into orbit.
She wanted to avoid getting
involved in your conflict.
So we came in on a shuttlecraft
that would avoid
immediate detection
by the Numiri.
I hid behind
the limb of the moon
before I made a break
for your defense perimeter.
By the time
their sensors picked us up,
they didn't
have a chance to catch us.
Well done!
Finished already?
The meat doesn't
taste right.
TOLEN:
Well...
we do have a lot of work
to get done.
Perhaps we should begin.
KIM:
We went into the other room
and started to work
on the navigational beam
specifications.
It was pretty dry stuff--
you know, rewriting
baseline code algorithms.
Tom got bored.
He left us alone
for a while.
I guess he was with Mrs. Ren.
I know they saw each other
again the next day.
That was the night
Professor Ren was murdered.
Did you talk to Lieutenant
Paris after he was detained?
No, they never let me see him.
They interrogated me
for almost two days straight.
They asked me a lot
of questions
about the Numiri.
At first, they must have
thought we were Numiri agents
or something.
Professor Ren was the inventor
of Banean
warship technology.
He's completely exhausted.
Can some of this wait until
he's had a chance to rest?
We'll find out about Paris,
Mr. Kim.
Janeway to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
Set a course for the Banean
homeworld, Commander.
Aye, Captain.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You sent for me, Captain?
( sighs )
Lieutenant Paris has gotten
himself into trouble.
I'm taking this ship
into orbit
while we try
to sort things out.
Be prepared to be intercepted
by Numiri patrols.
They always try to
intimidate travelers
to the Banean planet.
The stakes are too high to send
a shuttlecraft this time.
I want to show our flag
to make it clear
we mean business.
I understand.
Based on your experience,
what can we expect
the Numiri to do
to "intimidate" us?
To be honest, whenever
I saw the Numiri coming,
I always left before
the intimidation began.
( laughing )
Before...
( clears throat )
Uh, however, uh, I know
from, uh, knowledgeable sources
that they have
directed-energy weapons
comparable to your own--
Uh, our own, that is--
Plus regenerative shields
that may even give them
a certain advantage over us
in a fire fight.
Tell me about them,
as a people.
Are they aggressive,
technical,
intellectual, emotional?
Anything that might help me
deal with them.
The Numiri
and the Banea
are quite different
from one another,
even though they once coexisted
on the same planet.
That's why I recommended
the Banea to you
in the first place.
The Numiri have a remarkably
covert society.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
On my way.
We're scanning a Numiri
vessel approaching.
They're at combat
readiness, Captain.
Shields up.
On screen.
Mr. Neelix?
A standard patrol vessel.
Curious.
Why?
I would have expected them
to send out
more than one tiny patrol
to meet a ship like this.
Let's hope it's
a positive sign.
Hail them.
They're responding.
JANEWAY:
Open a channel.
I am Captain
Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
What is your business
in this system?
One of my crewmen is being held
on the Banean planet.
We're on our way to investigate.
Consider this official notice
that you are entering
a war zone.
You do so at your own risk.
Understood.
Any attempt to provide
aid or supplies to the Banea
will be considered an act
of war against the Numiri.
You have my word that we intend
to remain neutral
in your conflict.
Our only interest
is in our own crewman.
Proceed.
Your activities
will be monitored.
Very, very curious.
In Numiri terms, that greeting
was downright friendly.
Have all security stations
remain at full alert.
Continue long-range scans for
Numiri patrols around the clock.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
Take us into orbit.
Captain, it's unfortunate
we must meet
under these circumstances.
My Chief
of Security--
Lieutenant Tuvok.
Please.
Exactly what are these
circumstances, Minister?
All we know is that
a member of our crew
has been accused
of murder.
Oh, I'm afraid he's been
more than just accused.
He's been convicted and punished
according to our law.
What form of punishment?
The perpetrator of a murder
is forced to relive the crime
through his victim's eyes.
How is this achieved?
I can have
our Chief Medical Officer
describe the procedure
in detail, if you wish.
We have the capability
of isolating memory engrams
in the brain.
We take them
from the final moments of life.
After they're used in the trial,
they're transplanted
into the perpetrator's brain.
These memories... are used
in the trial as evidence?
An artificial life-form
serves as host to the engrams
and testifies to their content.
In this case,
the victim's last memories
clearly show Mr. Paris
caught in...
an embarrassing episode
with Mrs. Ren.
An argument ensues.
Paris is then seen by the
victim's own eyes killing him.
The evidence of his guilt
is incontrovertible.
Captain.
Are you all right, Tom?
I've been better.
May we speak
to him alone?
Of course.
( sighs )
That rehab colony
back in New Zealand
doesn't seem so bad
right now.
Lieutenant, did you murder
Professor Ren?
No.
But the victim's
own eyes identified...
You don't have
to tell me
what the victim's own
eyes saw, Captain.
I don't understand it
either,
but I did not kill him.
Were you having improper
relations with his wife?
Their marriage was over.
She told Ren they were finished
the same day he was killed.
That does not answer
my question.
Nothing happened between us.
Almost nothing.
Tom...
it's very important
you tell us everything.
Harry said you spent
some time with Mrs. Ren
while he and the Professor
were working.
I was bored.
You know how it is when
two science guys get together.
I came out of the other room,
looked over
and saw her in the atrium.
( chuckles )
Her eyes were
a million kilometers away--
Staring at stars I'd just
flown by the day before.
Smoking is a bad habit.
My species gave it up
centuries ago
when we finally got it into
our heads it was killing us.
You must be a very
superior species.
That's... not what I meant.
Maybe I kill myself slowly
because I don't have the courage
to do it quickly.
Now, why would you go and
say a thing like that?
Don't.
What?
Don't get involved, Lieutenant.
I was just
trying to...
You'll be sorry.
Look, I was just bored to tears
in the other room,
and I thought
you might like to talk.
Why don't you go ahead
and ask me?
Ask you what?
What you've been wanting
to ask me all night...
what they all want to ask me.
Why I'd marry a man
old enough to be my father.
I'd be lying if I said
I hadn't been wondering.
He was good to me.
A lot of other men weren't.
That sounds like
a good enough reason to me.
He's a good man.
I would never do anything
to hurt him.
I guess...
that makes you
a good woman.
"Good" can get very...
boring.
No, Tom! Don't.
No. I...
Stop! No!
What's going on?
No!
Apparently, he's entering
another cycle.
( yelling )
Is this normal?
We had some problems
integrating the Banean engrams
into his alien neurology.
This is the first time
he's lost consciousness
since the implant.
I'd like to take him
back with us
to our medical
facility.
I'm sorry, but I
can't authorize that.
Perhaps we should consider
her request, Minister.
We don't want to risk
general synaptic failure.
Their doctors might be
better suited to stabilize
his condition.
All right, but you're not
to leave orbit with him.
Minister, we don't intend
to leave orbit
until we prove his innocence.
Away team to Voyager.
Three to beam up.
DOCTOR:
It's medicine clearly
beyond anything
we've ever encountered before.
What bothers me the most
is the neural pathway damage
it seems to be causing.
It appears to be progressive.
Then this punishment
could actually be causing
serious brain damage.
How long it might be
before he's seriously affected,
I really have no idea.
I would appreciate
receiving a copy
of your neurological
analysis, Doctor.
It's extremely technical.
To the layman, it would be
virtually indecipherable.
Nevertheless, I will want
to examine it in detail.
This might be the basis
for an appeal of the sentence,
don't you think?
Perhaps.
However, before the neural
implants were developed,
the Banean punishment for murder
was lethal injection.
It is possible
they would view that
as the only alternative sentence
in this case.
Will he regain
consciousness?
I believe so,
but each time
the cycle repeats,
I'm afraid his brain will
take another damaging blow.
When he wakes up,
I will require
an autonomic response analysis
while I question him
again, Doctor.
Do you really think
Tom would lie to us?
As an investigator,
I do not have the freedom
to ignore any possibility.
Mr. Paris
maintains his innocence,
yet the victim has identified
him from the grave,
and the victim's wife
has testified against him
at the trial.
Someone is obviously lying.
An ARA will tell us
if it is Mr. Paris.
I'll have it ready for you.
In the meantime,
Captain,
I request permission
to return to the surface.
What do you have in mind,
Tuvok?
I would like to examine
the murder scene
and speak with Mrs. Ren.
Mrs. Ren?
Yes?
I'm Lieutenant Tuvok
of the Starship Voyager.
Would you mind if I asked
you a few questions?
Are you a friend
of Tom's?
I am the Starfleet
Chief of Security
investigating
his alleged participation
in your husband's murder.
( dog growls )
Stop it, Neeka.
She just doesn't like strangers.
Based on your testimony,
I assume this is
where the murder occurred.
Yes, right there.
I had to have a professional
cleaning crew
come in to remove
the bloodstain.
You chose to remain
in the house
after an act
of such violence occurred?
This has been my home for
over ten years, Mr. Tuvok.
Do you really find that
so hard to believe?
I am a Vulcan, Mrs. Ren.
By nature, we are
a dispassionate people.
It is rare to encounter someone
as dispassionate as we are.
Dispassionate?
Is that how I seem to you?
I think you'd get an argument
from Tom Paris.
Can I get you a drink?
Thank you, no.
Mind if I have one?
Please.
You testified at the trial
that you and your husband
had an argument the afternoon
before he was killed.
I never said there was
an argument, Lieutenant.
Have you ever had
to end a marriage?
No.
Are you married?
My wife and I have been married
for 67 years.
I'm sure she's a fine,
dispassionate woman.
( chuckles )
I hope you never have
to find out for yourself,
but I can tell you,
ending a marriage...
it's a quiet thing.
The arguments are long over
and there's really nothing much
left to say at all.
May I ask why you decided
at this time
to end your marriage
to Professor Ren?
Because I was attracted
to another man.
I didn't want to deceive
my husband.
That other man
was Lieutenant Paris?
Lieutenant Paris would have been
departing this planet
in a few days,
and yet, you left your husband
of ten years for him.
Meeting Tom
gave me the push I needed.
I already knew in my heart
that it was time to start over.
Exactly when did you
see Mr. Paris
on the day of the murder?
I went to see him
at the Engineering Institute
after I talked with my husband.
Once I was free, I knew
he wanted to be with me.
How did you know?
A woman knows, Lieutenant.
He left his friend Harry
to finish
the technical research
and walked me home.
We were caught in a cloudburst
on the way.
Oh, I'm completely
soaked.
There must be a centimeter
of water in my boots.
Here, let me help you.
We shouldn't.
It's okay.
He knows it's over.
But you're still
a married woman.
I haven't been married
for years, Tom.
To him, I'm a friend,
a companion.
He hasn't treated me
like a woman since...
It must have been
the day of the eclipse
four years ago.
Eclipse?
He was very excited
by the eclipse.
Don't ask me why.
Our timing's
just a little off.
You'll be gone
in a few days.
This is the only
time we've got.
Let me make you something
to warm you up.
I love to drink
Marob root tea
on rainy afternoons.
I made some tea.
We talked for a while.
Then we went out to the atrium
to watch the storm...
and the rest you know.
Did you leave the room
at any time during the fight
between your husband
and Lieutenant Paris?
I saw Tom murder
my husband, Mr. Tuvok.
I tried to stop him.
I couldn't.
CHAKOTAY:
Voyager to Tuvok.
This is Lieutenant Tuvok.
Mr. Paris has regained
consciousness.
I thought you'd want to know.
Thank you.
I'll be returning shortly.
Tuvok out.
Thank you for your
help, Mrs. Ren.
Lieutenant.
When you see Tom...
would you tell him that I...
forgive him?
Everything she told you
is true.
Except I don't remember
going into the atrium
or anything else after that.
The last thing
you remember is?
Sitting with her,
drinking tea...
talking about the sensual
effects of eclipses...
After that I must have
fallen asleep.
When I woke up, I was in a cell.
He's telling you
the truth.
Was there any evidence
of a sedative in his system
when he returned here?
The Banean medical
authorities checked him.
They didn't find any
drugs in his blood.
Most narcotics would have
been gone from his system
by the time he got to me.
Chakotay to Tuvok.
You're needed on the Bridge.
We're under attack
by Numiri patrols.
On my way, Commander.
Evasive pattern Beta 140.
Dual attack mode.
Evasive pattern confirmed.
They're attempting to lock
a tractor beam on us.
That is a standard tactic
for the Numiri
when they intend
to board your vessel.
Well, at least now
you know
I was telling the truth
about them, Captain.
Although I take no pleasure
in being right, mind you.
But why now?
Why an unprovoked attack?
What are they after?
The Numiri have never needed
an excuse to attack anyone.
Shields at 90 percent
and holding.
Commander, prepare to initiate
attack maneuver Kappa 010.
Captain, if you
don't mind...
there's a Maquis trick
we sometimes use
to get out of
situations like this.
Be my guest.
B'Elanna, remember
Teluridian IV?
The two Starfleet runabouts?
I'm with you.
Blowing out
the dorsal phase emitters.
Torres to Engineering.
Go ahead.
Vent a couple
of LN-2 exhaust conduits
along the dorsal emitters.
Make it look like
we're in serious trouble.
Understood.
Cut all engines.
Engines off-line.
Tuvok, lock phasers on
their navigational deflectors.
Acknowledged.
Numiri ships are closing.
4,000 kilometers.
Not to belittle Maquis tactics,
Commander, but this is
a very old trick.
It worked against those
Starfleet runabouts.
You're lucky I wasn't
commanding one of them.
2,000 kilometers.
CHAKOTAY:
Besides,
out here in the
Delta Quadrant,
every old trick
is new again.
1,500 kilometers.
They're sending out
tractor beams again.
That's our cue.
Fire phasers.
Engage impulse engines.
Both Numiri vessels
are disabled, Captain.
That's one trick you won't
be able to use again
when we get back.
I have more.
Cancel Red Alert.
Take us into high orbit.
NEELIX:
Captain.
More Numiri will be coming.
I promise you.
Mr. Tuvok, any progress
with your investigation?
TUVOK:
Based on the ARA,
I am convinced
Lieutenant Paris
believes what he is saying.
However, I can offer no tangible
evidence on his behalf.
Considering the urgency
of the situation,
I believe
the only logical alternative
at this time
is to witness the crime myself.
Yourself?
I propose a mind-meld
with Lieutenant Paris.
A-a what?
What, what did he say?
A mind what?
Let me tell you something,
Lieutenant.
Believe it or not,
I know more about
mind-melds than you do.
I know what every
Vulcan doctor has said
in every study of mind-melds,
and I still cannot tell you
what will happen
if you do this.
If these cycles cause damage
to a human brain,
there's no telling
what the risk might be
to a Vulcan.
I've examined your neurological
reports, Doctor,
and I believe the risk
is acceptable.
Tuvok...
Captain...
the answers I seek
can only be found
in the eyes of the murdered man.
It may be our only chance to
prove Lieutenant Paris innocent.
Tom?
Tolen!
TOLEN:
Now I understand.
I'd better be
on my way.
You don't have to go, Tom.
He's got no right.
TOLEN:
No right?
This is my home!
You come into my home
and steal my wife,
and I have no right?
That's not the way
it happened.
We'll see what your Captain
has to say about this.
When I'm finished with you,
you'll never wear
that uniform again.
PARIS:
I can't let you do that.
No, Tom, don't. Stop! No!
( Tolen yells )
( Tolen groaning )
The cycle's ended.
No neural damage
that I can detect.
Captain, I must consult
with Ensign Kim immediately.
With Kim? Why?
I assume he has access
to Professor Ren's research.
I believe it will explain
not only why Lieutenant Paris
has been accused of a murder
he did not commit,
but also why the Numiri
chose to attack us.
His condition has
continued to deteriorate.
He'll have serious
brain damage
if the implants
are not removed.
We are not a barbaric
people, Captain.
This was meant as punishment
not torture.
I see no alternative but to
remove the implants, do you?
There is no legal
precedent, of course,
but we can petition
the courts immediately.
I cannot assure you'll find
an alternative sentence
more to your liking.
We're still committed to proving
his innocence, Minister.
When do you intend
to return him to our custody?
Due to the nature
of his condition,
we're concerned
that our transporting device
might cause
further medical complications.
So we're sending him back
by shuttlecraft.
They'll leave this ship
in one hour.
I'll make the necessary
preparations.
This is all
your fault, you know?
My fault?
Yeah, I consider you
the conscience I never had.
You're supposed to keep me
on the straight and narrow.
I tried to warn you.
( chuckles ):
Funny, so did she.
If it had been me,
I would have stayed
as far away
from her as possible.
Someday it will
be you, Harry.
You'll meet her,
and you'll know it's wrong from
the first moment you see her.
And you'll know there's nothing
you can do about it.
( console beeps )
Here they come.
Numiri patrol approaching,
bearing 067 mark 24.
Red Alert.
On screen.
Range, 100,000 kilometers
and closing.
They're changing course,
Captain.
CHAKOTAY:
They're going straight
for the shuttle
just as you said
they would, Lieutenant.
( beeping )
Shuttle to Voyager.
They've locked a
tractor beam on us.
Offer no resistance, Harry.
Acknowledged.
PARIS:
Hey, Tuvok.
I know it's
a little late to ask,
but you're sure you've got the
logic of this thing worked out?
If I am incorrect,
we will know it shortly.
Well, that makes me feel
a whole lot better.
( loud clunk )
We're being boarded.
NUMIRI:
He's the one.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
You have illegally seized
one of our shuttlecraft.
I warned you that you were
entering a war zone
at your own risk.
Yes.
We appreciated that warning
and took
appropriate precautions.
If you read the sensor readouts
in front of you,
you will see that the shuttle
is carrying 40 tons
of thalmerite explosives--
enough to destroy your ship.
I'm prepared to detonate
those explosives in 30 seconds
if you do not release
our vessel.
End transmission.
The shuttle's being released.
The Numiri ship is withdrawing.
Tractor the shuttle
and take us into low orbit.
Cancel Red Alert.
Mr. Paris, how soon
before your next cycle?
Seven hours.
That should be enough time
to clear this up.
Mr. Tuvok,
this is your show now.
With your permission,
I would like to invite
all interested parties
to meet at the scene of
the murder in two hours.
I'll invite the Minister myself.
Lieutenant Paris was not
the man Professor Ren saw
before he was murdered.
Not the man...
But it was clearly
established at the trial.
It is true.
Paris' image was seen
in the memories
examined during the trial.
However,
that is because someone
altered the engrams
from Professor Ren's brain.
But that simply isn't possible
for this procedure.
I would suggest, sir,
that there is no such thing
as a technology that is
entirely safe from tampering.
You're forgetting one thing.
I was here and I saw him do it.
On the contrary,
I have not forgotten
your statement, Mrs. Ren.
However, I now know
it is clearly false.
PARIS:
Just what was
in that tea
you gave me, Lidell?
Is this just idle speculation,
or do you have some evidence?
Mr. Paris, would you please
stand next to Mrs. Ren?
What for?
If you wouldn't mind.
The man Professor Ren
observed with his wife
was virtually equal
in height to her.
Clearly, Lieutenant Paris
is several centimeters taller.
How do you know
what my husband saw?
Vulcans have the ability
to meld telepathically
with another's mind.
I observed
your husband's memories
as Lieutenant Paris
went through his cycle.
I watched as the killer
stabbed Professor Ren
right here,
through the intercostal space
between the eighth
and ninth right ribs--
the exact location
of the Banean heart.
The killer clearly knew
Banean anatomy.
Lieutenant Paris did not.
Are we supposed to take
your word for all of this?
There is additional evidence.
For example,
we can now say for certain
that Professor Ren
was murdered by a Numiri agent.
What?
Lieutenant,
did you notice the stream
of symbols and numbers
that were superimposed
on the images?
Symbols?
Well, yeah,
I guess I did.
I didn't know
what they meant.
I thought they were
part of the procedure.
In researching
this procedure,
I found no other reference
to this phenomenon.
I have now confirmed
that these symbols and numbers
were equations
taken from Professor Ren's
weapons research.
Someone intended them to be
delivered to the Numiri.
You're saying somebody
used his brain
to send secret data
to our enemy?
He was a logical courier.
The Numiri agents knew he could
leave the planet's surface
without raising suspicion.
The Numiri made two attempts
to gain access to Mr. Paris.
They attacked just after
he returned to Voyager,
and then again
when he was in the shuttle.
Someone on the surface
had to be informing the Numiri
of Lieutenant Paris' movements.
Do you know who did this?
You knew when Mr. Paris
would be in transit, Minister.
But the doctor is the one
who encouraged you
to release him to our custody.
He is also
the one
who performed
the implant procedure.
I know of no one else who had
the opportunity and knowledge
to carry out this plan.
I'm not going
to listen to any of this.
I really would like you
to listen, Doctor.
Would you please
stand again, Mrs. Ren.
So we're the
same height.
It proves nothing.
I never saw this woman
prior to the death
of her husband.
I was never even in
this house before today.
You forget the other witness
who was here
on the night of the murder,
Doctor.
Would you mind
asking her to come in?
( whining squeakily )
TUVOK:
It appears
that you are no stranger
to Neeka, Doctor.
He lied to me, Tom.
No one was supposed
to get hurt.
You know I could never
do anything to hurt you.
Yeah.
You could.
( quiet laughter
and conversation )
Tuvok.
Mr. Paris.
There are some who'd say
you risked my future
on the eyewitness
identification of a dog.
It seemed a necessary step
to ensure a
truthful resolution.
Well... I appreciate
you sticking up for me.
I owe you one.
I conducted
a criminal investigation.
If you had been guilty,
I assure you
I would have pursued the truth
just as vigilantly.
You have no debt to me,
Mr. Paris.
( sighs )
How come I always see you
down here
eating alone, Lieutenant?
I prefer to read
rather than engage in...
What do humans call it--
short talk?
Close enough.
You don't make
many friends that way.
Perhaps.
Well, like it or not,
you've made one today,
Mr. Tuvok.