CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 48623.5.
THERE ARE 246 ELEMENTS
KNOWN TO FEDERATION SCIENCE.
WE BELIEVE WE HAVE
JUST DISCOVERED THE 247th
INSIDE THE RING SYSTEM
OF A CLASS-D PLANET.
THE ELEMENT HAS
AN UNUSUALLY LARGE ATOMIC MASS--
OVER 550 NUCLEONS.
AND THE RATINGS ARE CONSTANT.
THE ELEMENT APPEARS
TO BE STABLE.
A STABLE TRANSURANIC ELEMENT
INSIDE A NATURAL ENVIRONMENT.
THIS IS A FIRST.
CAN YOU IMAGINE WHAT WE COULD
MAKE WITH THIS STUFF?
PROBE CASINGS THAT COULD GO INTO
THE CORE OF A SUN.
ULTRATHIN REACTOR SHIELDING.
THAT'S ASSUMING WE CAN MINE IT.
ENSIGN, TRY AND LOCATE
THE HIGHEST CONCENTRATION
OF THE ELEMENT.
Kim:
THE ELEMENT IS PRESENT
IN MOST OF THE ASTEROIDS
THAT COMPRISE THE RINGS.
I CAN ISOLATE A SAMPLE
AND BEAM IT ABOARD.
OR BETTER YET,
MAYBE WE COULD GET A FIRST-HAND
LOOK AT THIS ELEMENT
IN ITS NATURAL
ENVIRONMENT.
IT LOOKS LIKE MOST
OF THESE ASTEROIDS
SUPPORT CLASS-M
ATMOSPHERES.
GOOD IDEA. COMMANDER,
YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
MR. KIM, WOULD YOU
LIKE TO JOIN US?
I WOULDN'T MISS IT, SIR.
THE HIGHEST CONCENTRATION
IS ABOUT 30 METERS
DIRECTLY AHEAD.
I'M PICKING UP
A LARGE CAVERN IN THERE.
THE READINGS ARE...
WHAT THE HELL IS THIS?
IT'S ORGANIC.
SOME KIND OF
BIOPOLYMER RESIDUE.
I WANT TO SEE
WHAT'S AHEAD.
THE READINGS ARE HIGHER
OVER HERE
BUT I STILL CAN'T FIND
THE SOURCE OF THE...
( gasps )
COMMANDER?
CLASS FIVE HUMANOID.
IT APPEARS TO BE DEAD.
CAPTAIN, THERE ARE
18 BODIES HERE--
ALL HUMANOID--
11 MALE, 7 FEMALE.
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL,
THEY'RE IN VARIOUS STAGES
OF DECOMPOSITION.
SOME HAVE BEEN HERE
FOR YEARS.
Others, no longer than
a few days.
In fact, one body arrived
less than 12 hours ago.
ARRIVED FROM WHERE?
I don't know, Captain.
BUT FROM THE POSITION
OF THE ARMS
I'D SAY WE'RE LOOKING AT SOME
KIND OF BURIAL SITE.
WHAT ABOUT THE ELEMENT
WE DISCOVERED?
IT'S EMANATING FROM
THEIR BODIES, CAPTAIN.
WE THINK IT'S SOME
KIND OF BYPRODUCT
of their decomposition process.
I recommend we leave these
bodies in peace, Captain.
HOWEVER, MR. KIM
HAS A DIFFERENT OPINION.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, CAPTAIN,
I HAVE TO DISAGREE WITH
THE COMMANDER.
THIS IS OUR FIRST CONTACT
WITH THIS RACE.
AND I THINK WE SHOULD BE
LEARNING ALL WE CAN ABOUT THEM.
It's a unique
anthropological opportunity.
I understand the chance for
scientific discovery, Captain,
BUT WHATEVER BELIEF THIS RACE
HAS, THEY CLEARLY MEANT
FOR THEIR DEAD
TO BE LEFT ALONE
AND I THINK WE SHOULD
RESPECT THAT.
I'M AFRAID I AGREE WITH
COMMANDER CHAKOTAY.
SET YOUR TRICORDERS
FOR PASSIVE SCANS.
I DON'T WANT
TO DISTURB ANYTHING.
Captain, the sanctity
OF THESE BODIES
SHOULD BE RESPECTED.
I RECOMMEND WE MAKE
VISUAL OBSERVATIONS ONLY.
NO TRICORDERS.
VERY WELL.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
Janeway out.
ALL RIGHT.
THE ONLY SENSORS YOU
HAVE LEFT ARE YOUR EYES.
CONCENTRATE
ON DETAILS.
WE'LL HAVE TO DO
A THOROUGH REPORT
WHEN WE GET BACK.
COMMANDER, THANKS
FOR LETTING ME
VOICE MY OPINION
TO THE CAPTAIN.
I REMEMBER THE FIRST TIME
I WENT ON A
TOMB EXCAVATION
ON KTARIA SEVEN.
I WANTED TO KEEP A MEMENTO
OF THE EXPERIENCE.
SO I PICKED UP A ROCK
FROM THE BURIAL SITE.
ONLY I FOUND OUT LATER
IT WASN'T JUST A ROCK.
WHAT WAS IT?
IT WAS A SACRED STONE.
THE KTARIANS LAY THOUSANDS
OF THEM IN THE TOMB.
EACH ONE REPRESENTS
A SPECIAL PRAYER.
WITHOUT REALIZING IT
I HAD DESECRATED
THAT MAN'S GRAVE.
WELL...
I THINK I'VE FOUND OUT
ABOUT ALL I CAN WITH MY EYES.
REALLY? WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED
ABOUT THIS CULTURE SO FAR?
THEY LIKE TO BURY THEIR DEAD
ON ASTEROIDS.
THAT'S ABOUT ALL I CAN TELL
WITHOUT A TRICORDER.
NO ARTIFACTS,
NO INSCRIPTIONS.
JUST SOME NAKED DEAD PEOPLE.
YOU'RE LOOKING,
BUT YOU'RE NOT SEEING.
THE FACT THAT THEY'RE NAKED
SAYS A LOT.
IT MEANS THIS RACE
DOESN'T BELIEVE IN
DRESSING THE DECEASED.
AND THE LACK OF ARTIFACTS
COULD INDICATE
THEY DON'T BELIEVE
ANY WORLDLY GOODS
CAN BE TAKEN INTO
THE AFTERLIFE.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK
THEY BELIEVE IN
AN AFTERLIFE AT ALL?
LOOK AT THE POSITION
OF THE ARMS AND HANDS.
THE BODIES HAVE BEEN ARRANGED
IN POSES OF SERENITY
AND THEY APPEAR TO BE WRAPPED IN
THE SAME BIOPOLYMER RESIDUE
WE FOUND OUT IN THE
PASSAGEWAY--
ALL INDICATIONS THAT THIS
CULTURE
HAS A GREAT DEAL OF RITUAL
ASSOCIATED WITH
THE DISPOSING OF THE DEAD.
THAT NORMALLY INDICATES
SOME BELIEF IN THE AFTERLIFE.
THE KLINGONS BELIEVE
IN AN AFTERLIFE
BUT THERE'S NO
BURIAL RITUAL.
THEY JUST DISPOSE
OF THE CORPSE
BY THE MOST EFFICIENT
MEANS POSSIBLE.
GOOD POINT.
HOWEVER, SOME ARCHEOLOGICAL DIGS
ON THE KLINGON...
( high-pitched whine )
TRICORDERS.
A DIMENSIONAL DISTORTION
IS FORMING.
SOME KIND OF
SUBSPACE VACUOLE.
CHAKOTAY TO VOYAGER.
EMERGENCY BEAM-OUT.
Janeway:
We're having trouble
locking onto your signals.
STAND BY.
HAVE EVERYONE STAND
CLOSER TOGETHER.
I'M GOING TO TRY A BLIND
BEAM-OUT
centered on your com signal.
ACKNOWLEDGED. ENERGIZE!
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER ROOM
THREE. DO YOU HAVE THEM?
Subspace distortions
FROM THE VACUOLE ARE INTERFERING
with the transporter lock.
I'm attempting
to compensate.
OKAY. I THINK I'VE GOT THEM.
CHAKOTAY AND LIEUTENANT TORRES
ARE ABOARD.
SO IS ONE OF
THE HUMANOID BODIES
but there's no sign
of Ensign Kim.
SCAN THE ASTEROID.
NO LIFE SIGNS, CAPTAIN.
I'M BROADENING THE SCAN.
NOTHING. HE IS NOWHERE IN
THE ENTIRE ASTEROID FIELD.
SESKA, INITIATE EMERGENCY
TRANSPORT PROCEDURE 21 ALPHA.
I'M ALREADY ON IT, CAPTAIN.
IT'S NO USE.
HIS PATTERN'S GONE,
and the subspace vacuole
has disappeared.
I'm looking at
the transporter logs.
MY ONLY GUESS IS HE WAS
PULLED INTO THE VACUOLE.
THIS ISN'T ONE OF THE BODIES
WE FOUND IN THE CAVERN.
IT'S SOMEONE ELSE.
THIS BODY MIGHT HAVE COME OUT
OF THE VACUOLE
AT THE SAME TIME
KIM WAS TAKEN IN.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'M SHOWING SIGNS
OF ELECTRICAL ACTIVITY
IN THE BRAIN.
IT LOOKS LIKE SHE DIED
JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO.
WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO REVIVE HER.
IF WE CAN, WE MIGHT
GET SOME ANSWERS.
WE CAN'T INTERFERE
WITH THIS WOMAN'S
NATURAL PROCESS OF DEATH.
WHAT DO YOU SUGGEST
WE DO, COMMANDER?
KIM'S GONE.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE
WHO MIGHT BE ABLE
TO TELL US
WHAT HAPPENED.
BEAM US DIRECTLY
TO SICK BAY.
Seska:
Aye, Commander.
DEATH IS THE END OF THIS LIFE
BUT IT IS ALSO THE BEGINNING
OF A NEW JOURNEY.
PTERA WILL NOW THRIVE
IN THE NEXT EMANATION.
THIS IS BOTH HER SACRED DUTY
AND HER GREAT PRIVILEGE.
All:
ELER'ATAH.
AS SHE BEGINS HER TRANSITION
WE PROMISE
TO CARRY MEMORIES OF HER
SO THAT WHEN WE ENTER THE...
( banging )
Kim:
HELP! GET ME OUT OF HERE!
SHE'S... ALIVE!
DEACTIVATE THE CENOTAPH--
QUICKLY!
HERE IT IS.
THANKS.
A LOT OF MEMORIES IN THIS.
WE'RE SO PROUD
OF YOU, HATIL.
THIS IS SUCH
A GENEROUS, SELFLESS ACT.
IT'S MY LAST GIFT FOR YOU
AND THE CHILDREN.
AND IT'S ONE WE WILL
ALWAYS CHERISH.
( crying ):
BUT I'M STILL GOING
TO MISS YOU.
I KNOW.
I'LL MISS YOU TOO.
BUT I'LL SEE YOU
IN THE NEXT EMANATION
WHEN YOU'RE READY
TO JOIN ME.
GIVE MY LOVE
TO YOUR FATHER.
TELL HIM THAT THE
GARILI TREES HE PLANTED
HAVE BEEN IN BLOOM
FOR THREE YEARS STRAIGHT.
I WILL.
GOOD-BYE.
LIE DOWN.
IT'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
WE WON'T HARM YOU.
WHO IS THAT?
WE'RE NOT SURE YET.
WE THINK HE CAME
FROM THE NEXT EMANATION.
THE NEXT EMANATION?
YOU MEAN HE'S COME BACK?
COME BACK
FROM WHERE?
WE'VE CALLED FOR
THE THANATOLOGIST.
HE'LL BE HERE
ANY MOMENT.
I DON'T THINK
THERE SHOULD BE
ANY FURTHER DISCUSSION
ABOUT THIS UNTIL HE ARRIVES.
HOW DID YOU
GET HERE?
I'M NOT SURE.
I JUST SORT OF WOKE UP
INSIDE ONE OF THOSE PODS.
I WAS CONDUCTING
AN INVESTIGATION
ON AN ASTEROID.
WE FOUND SOME DEAD BODIES.
THEN THERE WAS SOME KIND
OF SUBSPACE PHENOMENON.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN
YOU SAW DEAD PEOPLE THERE?
( door opening )
I'M DOCTOR NERIA,
THE CHIEF THANATOLOGIST
OF THIS FACILITY.
ENSIGN HARRY KIM OF
THE FEDERATION STARSHIP VOYAGER.
I SEE.
WHAT RACE ARE YOU FROM?
WE CALL OURSELVES HUMAN.
WE COME FROM A PLANET
CALLED EARTH
IN A DISTANT PART
OF THE GALAXY.
HE SAID HE SAW DEAD
PEOPLE ON AN ASTEROID.
DEAD?
LOOK, CAN YOU TELL
ME WHERE I AM?
DOCTOR, WHAT DOES
THIS MEAN?
REST, HATIL.
THERE'S NO NEED
FOR CONCERN.
MAY I SPEAK TO YOU
PRIVATELY, ENSIGN HARRY?
JUST HARRY'S FINE.
WE ARE THE VHNORI
AND THIS IS OUR HOMEWORLD.
WE WERE INVESTIGATING
ONE OF THE ASTEROIDS
IN THE RINGS
AROUND YOUR PLANET.
THERE ARE NO RINGS
AROUND OUR WORLD.
SO... THE SUBSPACE VACUOLE
MUST HAVE TRANSPORTED ME
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY STAR CHARTS
I COULD LOOK AT?
I'D LIKE TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE I AM NOW
IN RELATION TO WHERE I WAS.
WHERE YOU ARE NOW
IS IN THE WORLD
OF THE LIVING.
WHERE YOU CAME FROM WAS...
ANOTHER DIMENSION.
ANOTHER DIMENSION?
YES. YOU RETURNED
FROM THE NEXT EMANATION.
THE AFTERLIFE.
HOW WERE YOU ABLE
TO REVIVE HER?
IT'S A SIMPLE
PROCESS, REALLY.
SHE DIED OF A CANCEROUS GROWTH
ON THE BRAIN STEM.
I REMOVED THE TUMOR,
REPLICATED NEW NEURAL TISSUE
AND USED THE STANDARD STARFLEET
POSTMORTEM
RESUSCITATION TECHNIQUE FOR
A CLASS 5 LIFE FORM.
WHY WAS SHE COVERED
WITH THIS BIOPOLYMER?
SHE WASN'T COVERED
WITH IT EXACTLY.
THE BIOPOLYMER IS A BYPRODUCT
OF HER OWN TISSUES.
EXPLAIN.
AS HER TISSUES DECAYED,
THE CELL MEMBRANES BROKE DOWN
INTO A BIOPOLYMER RESIN,
WHICH WAS THEN EXCRETED BY
HER EPIDERMAL LAYER.
MY GUESS IS IT'S A
NATURAL DECOMPOSITION
PROCESS FOR THIS SPECIES.
SO THE OTHER BIOPOLYMER FIBERS
WE FOUND IN THE CAVERN...
WERE PROBABLY THE RESULT
OF OTHER BODIES
THAT HAD DECOMPOSED
AND LEFT A RESIDUAL MEMBRANE.
IN ESSENCE, COMMANDER, YOU WERE
STROLLING THROUGH DEAD BODIES.
CAN YOU WAKE HER?
YES, OF COURSE.
KES, 2cc's OF NETINALINE.
HELLO.
Janeway:
I KNOW THIS MUST BE
VERY CONFUSING FOR YOU,
BUT YOU ARE ALL RIGHT.
MY NAME IS
KATHRYN JANEWAY.
I'M PTERA.
WHERE'S MY BROTHER?
YOUR BROTHER?
I'M AFRAID
HE'S NOT HERE.
BUT HE'S SUPPOSED TO BE HERE.
THEY'RE ALL SUPPOSED TO BE HERE.
PTERA, WE WERE
ABLE TO REMOVE
THE TUMOR FROM YOUR BRAIN.
YOU'RE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
WE REVIVED YOU...
THIS IS
THE NEXT EMANATION?
THIS IS THE AFTERLIFE?
NO. NO, IT'S NOT.
YOU'RE ON A STARSHIP.
THIS CAN'T BE RIGHT.
MY BROTHER'S SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE.
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
LET ME EXPLAIN.
NO!
NO. GET AWAY FROM ME.
THIS ISN'T RIGHT!
THIS CAN'T BE RIGHT!
( screaming )
YOU'RE SAYING THERE WAS A
WOMAN IN HERE
JUST BEFORE I ARRIVED?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HER NAME WAS PTERA.
SHE WAS DYING
OF A TUMOROUS LESION
TO HER MIDBRAIN.
DYING?
SO SHE WASN'T DEAD YET?
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
SHE DIDN'T DIE UNTIL
THE CENOTAPH WAS ACTIVATED.
THAT'S THE PURPOSE
OF THE CENOTAPH--
IT TERMINATES
A PERSON'S LIFE
JUST BEFORE THE APPEARANCE
OF A SPECTRAL RUPTURE
AND THEN IT
ALLOWS THEIR BODY
TO BE TAKEN
TO THE NEXT EMANATION.
SPECTRAL RUPTURE...
WELL... I CAN SHOW YOU.
THIS LOOKS LIKE WHAT WE WOULD
CALL A SUBSPACE VACUOLE.
DOES THE CENOTAPH
CREATE THESE RUPTURES?
NO. THEY'RE NATURAL
OCCURRENCES--
ONCE EVERY SIX HOURS.
THIS ENTIRE COMPLEX
WAS BUILT ON THIS SITE
BECAUSE A SPECTRAL RUPTURE
OCCURS HERE.
WE HAVE THOUSANDS
OF SUCH SITES ON OUR WORLD.
FORGIVE MY CURIOSITY, HARRY,
BUT YOU ARE THE FIRST PERSON
EVER TO COME BACK
FROM THE AFTERLIFE.
I HAVE QUITE
A FEW QUESTIONS.
YOU SAID
THAT YOU SAW DEAD BODIES?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE WERE 7 FEMALES,
11 MALES.
SOME OF THE BODIES
HAD BEEN THERE FOR YEARS.
OTHERS JUST FOR A FEW DAYS.
ARE YOU SAYING THAT WHEN WE DIE
WE GO TO SOME ASTEROID
AND DECOMPOSE?
WELL...
THAT'S WHAT
IT LOOKED LIKE TO US.
THESE BODIES...
DID YOU PERFORM ANY KIND OF
BIOSCANS ON THEM?
WAS THERE ANY SPECIFIC
MEDICAL DATA THAT
YOU CAN REMEMBER?
DOCTOR, MAYBE I SHOULD
JUST STOP RIGHT THERE.
THIS IS WHAT MY PEOPLE CALL
A FIRST CONTACT SITUATION
AND WE'VE LEARNED
TO BE VERY CAREFUL
ABOUT HOW MUCH WE TELL
ALIEN CULTURES WE'VE JUST MET.
I WOULD LIKE TO START
A COMPLETE BIOANALYSIS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
IF YOU'LL JUST FOLLOW
DR. RANORA.
BIOANALYSIS?
LOOK, ALL I WANT TO DO
IS GET BACK TO MY SHIP,
AND I THINK THERE
MIGHT BE A WAY TO USE
THIS SPECTRAL RUPTURE
OF YOURS TO...
YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU ARE OUR FIRST GLIMPSE
INTO WHAT LIES BEYOND DEATH.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO LET THIS
OPPORTUNITY PASS US BY.
Chakotay:
WE'VE COMPLETED OUR ANALYSIS
OF THE RING SYSTEM.
OUR SENSORS HAVE DETECTED
OVER 200,000 ALIEN BODIES
ON VARIOUS ASTEROIDS
IN THE RINGS.
FROM WHAT WE CAN TELL
A SUBSPACE VACUOLE
APPEARS ABOUT EVERY TWO HOURS
DEPOSITS A BODY,
AND THEN DISAPPEARS.
WE NEED TO FOCUS ON
THOSE VACUOLES.
CONCENTRATE ON TRYING
TO PROBE THEM
WITH A HIGH-RESOLUTION SCAN.
SEE IF YOU CAN FIND
ANY SIGN OF MR. KIM.
Zimmerman:
Sick bay to Captain Janeway.
GO AHEAD.
Our guest
has regained consciousness
and she's a little calmer
this time.
I'M ON MY WAY.
YOU HAVE THE BRIDGE.
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
I'M SORRY. I CAN'T
TELL YOU ANYTHING MORE.
YOU'VE TOLD ME
QUITE A BIT.
AT LEAST NOW I HAVE AN IDEA
OF WHAT MIGHT
HAVE HAPPENED TO MR. KIM.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
WELL, I'D LIKE SOME ANSWERS.
ABOUT WHAT?
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS
TO MY PEOPLE WHEN WE DIE.
WE'RE NOT SURE, EXACTLY,
BUT FROM WHAT WE DO KNOW,
THE VACUOLES
DEPOSIT THE BODIES
ON THE ASTEROIDS
IN THIS RING SYSTEM.
AND THEN WHAT?
I'M NOT SURE WHAT YOU MEAN.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO EVOLVE
INTO A HIGHER LEVEL
OF CONSCIOUSNESS WHEN WE DIE--
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO GAIN A GREATER
UNDERSTANDING OF THE UNIVERSE.
ALL OF OUR QUESTIONS
ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE ANSWERED.
PTERA, I KNOW THIS
MUST BE FRIGHTENING FOR YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
A VERY TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
IT WOULD FRIGHTEN ME,
BUT PLEASE TRY TO UNDERSTAND.
JUST BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE
THE ANSWERS TO YOUR QUESTIONS
DOESN'T MEAN THERE AREN'T ANY.
MY BROTHER...
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
I'D SEE HIM AGAIN.
I HAD SO MANY
THINGS TO TELL HIM
ABOUT HIS CHILDREN...
THE PEOPLE HE LEFT BEHIND...
BUT HE ISN'T HERE, IS HE?
HE'S...
SO, WHAT AM I SUPPOSED
TO DO NOW?
SPEND THE REST OF MY LIFE
ON THIS... THIS... STARSHIP?
PTERA, I AM GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER
TO FIGURE OUT
JUST HOW YOU GOT HERE
AND AS SOON AS I KNOW ANYTHING,
I WILL TELL YOU.
ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT.
MAYBE WE SHOULD
GET OUT OF SICK BAY.
LET YOU WALK AROUND FOR A WHILE;
CLEAR YOUR MIND.
MAYBE GET
SOMETHING TO EAT.
ARE YOU HUNGRY?
YES. ACTUALLY, I COULD USE
SOMETHING TO EAT.
WHAT WAS THAT?
JANEWAY TO BRIDGE. REPORT.
THERE'S SOME KIND
OF DIMENSIONAL DISTORTION
FORMING NEAR MAIN ENGINEERING,
CAPTAIN.
IT LOOKS LIKE A
SUBSPACE VACUOLE.
JANEWAY TO ENGINEERING.
B'ELANNA, WHAT'S GOING ON?
I'VE PINPOINTED THE LOCATION,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S RIGHT HERE IN ENGINEERING.
STAND BY.
HATIL, WHAT
ARE YOU SAYING?
I'M JUST NOT
SURE I'M READY
THAT'S ALL.
I... I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
NEITHER DO I.
IT'S JUST THAT I'M
STARTING TO WONDER
WHAT REALLY HAPPENS
WHEN WE DIE...
IF I'M REALLY
GOING ON
TO A HIGHER LEVEL
OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
THE ALIEN, WHAT HAS
HE BEEN TELLING YOU?
ALL HE'S DONE
IS MADE ME STOP AND THINK
ABOUT SOMETHING WE'VE
ALWAYS TAKEN FOR GRANTED.
AND NOW THAT I'VE
THOUGHT ABOUT IT
I'M NOT SO EAGER TO GO
THROUGH WITH IT ANYMORE.
HATIL, WE KNOW
NOTHING ABOUT HIM
OR WHY HE'S COME HERE,
OR WHY HE'S SPREADING LIES
ABOUT THE NEXT EMANATION.
ALL I KNOW
IS YOU CAN'T THROW AWAY
A LIFETIME OF BELIEF
BECAUSE OF HIM.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
TO THINK ANYMORE.
I'M SCARED, ARAYA.
IT'S GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
THINK ABOUT YOUR FATHER.
HE'S WAITING FOR YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU AT THE
TRANSFERENCE RITUAL.
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU ARE
OR WHERE YOU COME FROM
BUT YOU STAY AWAY
FROM MY HUSBAND.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO...
HARRY,
YOU HAVE TO FORGIVE MY WIFE.
SHE'S HAVING TROUBLE
UNDERSTANDING MY CONCERNS
ABOUT THE AFTERLIFE.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
I'M, UH...
GETTING READY TO DIE.
FORGIVE ME FOR ASKING AGAIN,
BUT CAN YOU TELL ME ANYTHING
ABOUT WHAT I MIGHT FIND
IN THE NEXT EMANATION?
EVERYONE KEEPS ASKING ME THAT
AND I JUST KEEP GIVING
THE SAME ANSWER.
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT YOU DO COME
FROM THE AFTERLIFE.
I COME FROM A DIFFERENT REALITY,
MAYBE ANOTHER DIMENSION
AND MAYBE IT IS YOUR AFTERLIFE.
I DON'T KNOW.
ALL I DO KNOW IS THAT THERE
ARE COUNTLESS BILLIONS OF
PEOPLE THERE WHO ARE BORN,
LIVE, AND DIE,
JUST LIKE YOU DO HERE.
BUT YOU DID SEE
MY PEOPLE THERE.
YOU SAID THEY WERE DEAD.
YES, BUT...
LOOK. FOR ALL I KNOW,
YOUR THANATOLOGISTS ARE RIGHT.
AND ALL I SAW WERE THE CORPOREAL
REMAINS OF YOUR PEOPLE,
AND YOU DO GO ON TO
A HIGHER CONSCIOUSNESS.
BUT IT'S, UH...
IT'S ALSO
POSSIBLE THAT...
THERE IS NO HIGHER
EXISTENCE FOR US--
THAT WHEN WE DIE, WE
SIMPLY CEASE TO EXIST.
I...
I REALLY CAN'T SAY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO YOUR PEOPLE AFTER THEY DIE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO MY PEOPLE AFTER THEY DIE.
DON'T YOU HAVE THANATOLOGISTS,
PEOPLE WHO STUDY DEATH?
WELL, SORT OF.
THERE HAVE CERTAINLY BEEN
MEDICAL EXPERTS...
PHILOSOPHERS, THEOLOGIANS,
WHO HAVE SPENT
A GREAT DEAL OF TIME
DEBATING WHAT HAPPENS
AFTER DEATH,
BUT NO ONE'S COME UP
WITH AN ANSWER YET.
MY PEOPLE HAVE COME
TO THINK OF DEATH
AS JUST ANOTHER STAGE
OF OUR EXISTENCE.
THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE
WHO ARE EVEN EAGER TO DIE.
IF THEY FEEL
DEPRESSED
OR LONELY IN THIS LIFE, THEY
SIMPLY MOVE ON TO THE NEXT ONE.
IS THAT WHY YOU'RE HERE?
BECAUSE YOU'RE
NOT HAPPY WITH YOUR LIFE?
EVER SINCE THE, UM...
ACCIDENT...
LIFE HASN'T BEEN EASY.
BUT I HAVE TO SAY THIS
IS MORE MY FAMILY'S IDEA
THAN IT IS MINE.
YOUR FAMILY.
I'M A BURDEN TO THEM RIGHT NOW.
IT TAKES A LOT OF THEIR TIME
AND RESOURCES TO CARE FOR ME
AND I CAN'T GIVE
MUCH BACK TO THEM.
SO THERE WAS A FAMILY MEETING,
AND IT WAS AGREED THAT...
I SHOULD MOVE ON
TO THE NEXT EMANATION.
YOU LOOK APPALLED.
IT'S NOT MY PLACE
TO JUDGE YOUR CULTURE,
BUT FROM MY PERSPECTIVE
IT'S A LITTLE CHILLING
TO HEAR THAT.
EVEN THOUGH THE FAMILY
DID IT OUT OF... LOVE...
AND EVERYONE WAS HAPPY FOR ME
AND THEY SAID THEY'D SEE ME
WHEN THEY GOT
TO THE NEXT EMANATION...
I HAVE TO ADMIT
THERE IS A LITTLE VOICE
INSIDE OF ME
THAT IS TERRIFIED OF DYING
AND SINCE
I'VE BEEN TALKING TO YOU...
THAT LITTLE VOICE
HAS STARTED TO GET...
LOUDER.
I'M READING ANOTHER VACUOLE
FORMING ON THE SHIP.
TUVOK, REMODULATING
THE SHIELD HARMONICS.
IT'S NO USE, CAPTAIN.
THE VACUOLE
IS STILL FORMING.
( high-pitched whine )
TAKE THE BODY
TO THE SHIP'S MORGUE.
( beeping )
THIS IS ODD.
THREE BODIES HAVE APPEARED
ON VOYAGER SO FAR,
AND EACH ONE OF THEM
HAS RELEASED SOME KIND
OF NEURAL ENERGY.
IN EVERY CASE,
THE ENERGY HAS PASSED
THROUGH THE HULL AND
OUT INTO THE RINGS.
THE ENERGY'S FREQUENCY
IS IDENTICAL
TO THE AMBIENT RADIATION
IN THE ASTEROID FIELD.
THE VACUOLES
ARE DISRUPTING
THE WARP CORE'S
MAGNETIC INTERLOCKS.
IT WON'T BE LONG BEFORE
WE LOSE ANTIMATTER CONTAINMENT.
THE VACUOLES HAVE ALL FORMED
WITHIN 20 METERS
OF THE WARP CORE.
THEY MIGHT BE
ATTRACTED TO IT.
JANEWAY TO BRIDGE.
MR. PARIS, LAY IN A COURSE.
I WANT TO GET AT LEAST
a half a light year away.
Warp seven.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
PARIS TO JANEWAY.
I'VE BROUGHT US OUT OF WARP.
WE'RE POINT SIX LIGHT-YEARS
FROM THE RING SYSTEM.
ANY OTHER
SUBSPACE VACUOLES FORMING?
NO.
THE MAGNETIC INTERLOCKS
HAVE STABILIZED.
I THINK WE'RE SAFE OUT HERE.
BEGIN WORKING
ON A WAY TO PROTECT
THE WARP CORE
FROM THESE VACUOLES.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
Kes:
SOMETIMES I COME IN HERE
AND JUST STARE OUT
AT THE STARS FOR HOURS.
I NEVER GET TIRED
OF LOOKING AT THEM.
WE WERE ALWAYS TOLD
WE WOULD SEE BEAUTIFUL SIGHTS
IN THE NEXT EMANATION,
COLORS, LIGHTS,
AND THAT WE WOULD
SEE THEM WITH NEW EYES
AND A NEW UNDERSTANDING.
BUT NOW...
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE OTHERS--
MY BROTHER...
MY FATHER...
AND EVERYONE BEFORE THEM.
PEOPLE DIE EVERY DAY
ON MY WORLD.
DO THEY ALL END UP
AS LIFELESS CORPSES?
WHEN PEOPLE DIE ON MY WORLD,
WE BURY THEM BENEATH THE SOIL
AND WE BELIEVE THAT THEIR COMRA
IS RELEASED INTO THE AFTERLIFE.
THEIR COMRA?
OUR SOUL, OUR SPIRIT,
THE ESSENCE OF OUR BEINGS.
MAYBE SOMETHING SIMILAR
HAPPENS TO YOU.
BUT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WE DON'T BELIEVE
IN ANY KIND OF SPIRIT.
WHEN WE DIE, WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO REAPPEAR AS PHYSICAL BEINGS
WITH ARMS AND LEGS.
THAT'S THE WHOLE POINT
OF SENDING OUR PEOPLE
THROUGH THE SPECTRAL RUPTURES.
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO TRAVEL ON TO
THE NEXT EMANATION AS OURSELVES
AND BE REUNITED
WITH OUR FAMILIES.
BUT NONE OF THAT IS TRUE...
IS IT?
( inhales deeply )
NONE OF THE PEOPLE I LOVE
ARE HERE.
I'M ALONE.
I DON'T BELONG HERE.
I CAN'T LIVE LIKE THIS.
PLEASE, CAN'T YOU SEND ME HOME?
I THINK THERE IS
ONLY ONE PERSON ON THIS SHIP
WHO COULD ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
GET YOU BACK HOME, PTERA.
ONCE WE LOCATE
OUR MISSING OFFICER
WE'RE HOPING HE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO TELL US ENOUGH TO...
WAIT A MINUTE, CAPTAIN. MAYBE
THERE IS A WAY
TO SEND PTERA HOME AND FIND
ENSIGN KIM AT THE SAME TIME.
EXPLAIN.
WHAT IF WE RECREATED
THE TRANSPORTER ACCIDENT?
IF IT'S TRUE THAT HARRY WAS
PULLED THROUGH THE VACUOLE
DURING TRANSPORT, WE MIGHT BE
ABLE TO REPRODUCE
THOSE CIRCUMSTANCES
AND SEND PTERA HOME.
WE COULD SEND PTERA THROUGH
WITH A SUBSPACE TRANSPONDER,
AND HOPE THE SIGNAL
WILL PENETRATE
THE DIMENSIONAL BARRIER, AND
ALLOW US TO
LOCK ON TO KIM
WITH A TRANSPORTER BEAM.
RIGHT.
SO I CAN GET HOME?
PTERA, YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT THERE'S NO GUARANTEE
THIS IS GOING TO WORK.
I UNDERSTAND THE RISK,
BUT I'VE ALREADY
BEEN DEAD ONCE
AND I'M PREPARED TO DIE AGAIN
IF NECESSARY.
SO IF THERE'S A CHANCE
I CAN GET HOME
I'M WILLING TO TAKE THE RISK.
ALL RIGHT.
COMMANDER, PREPARE
A SUBSPACE TRANSPONDER
AND TEACH PTERA
HOW TO USE IT.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL:
WE'VE RETURNED
TO THE RING SYSTEM
AND WE'RE PREPARING TO SEND
PTERA BACK TO HER DIMENSION.
LIEUTENANT TORRES HAS FOUND
A WAY TO TEMPORARILY PROTECT
THE WARP CORE
AGAINST THE VACUOLES
BUT SHE IS UNCERTAIN HOW LONG
HER MEASURES WILL BE EFFECTIVE.
YOU UNDERSTAND THE INSTRUCTIONS
FOR MR. KIM IF YOU FIND HIM?
YES.
WE'VE GOT ONE,
COMMANDER,
FORMING TEN METERS
BELOW US, DECK 13.
OKAY, LET'S SEE IF
YOUR DAMPENING FIELD
IS GOING TO PROTECT THE
WARP CORE.
THE FIELD IS FLUCTUATING
SLIGHTLY, BUT HOLDING.
ENGINEERING TO
TRANSPORTER ROOM THREE.
There's a vacuole forming on
Deck 13.
Magnetic interlocks are stable.
ACKNOWLEDGED.
I SEE THE VACUOLE. LOCKING ON.
GOOD LUCK, PTERA.
Seska:
I HAVE A TRANSPORTER LOCK.
ENERGIZING.
MATCHING HER PATTERN
TO THE SUBSPACE DISTORTIONS.
WAIT A MINUTE. THE VACUOLE
IS SHUTTING DOWN.
I CAN'T GET HER PATTERN THROUGH.
ABORT THE PROCEDURE.
PULL HER BACK.
I'M TRYING.
I'M LOSING HER PATTERN.
SHUNT EMERGENCY POWER
INTO BUFFER TANK FOUR.
THAT'S IT. I'VE GOT THE PATTERN.
SHE'S DEAD.
IS THERE ANY BRAIN ACTIVITY?
CAN WE REVIVE HER?
JANEWAY TO LIEUTENANT TORRES.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE HAVE TO LEAVE?
I'd say we're safe
for another two hours.
THAT GIVES US TWO HOURS
TO FIND MR. KIM.
WE'LL HAVE TO STAY WITHIN
HIGH-RANGE SCANNER RANGE.
PERFORM ANOTHER
SUBSPACE SCAN.
THIS TIME, EXTEND
THE SCAN RADIUS TO 10AU.
I'M ON MY WAY
TO ENGINEERING.
JANEWAY OUT.
Aye, Captain.
ENSIGN, BEAM HER
ONTO ONE OF THE ASTEROIDS.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
THAT'S WHERE SHE
WAS MEANT TO BE.
I HOPE YOU FIND
YOUR AFTERLIFE, PTERA.
WHY?
WE WANT TO MAKE
A MORE DETAILED SCAN
OF YOUR
MICROCELLULAR STRUCTURES
AND A COMPLETE EXAMINATION
OF YOUR NEURAL CHEMISTRY.
THIS FACILITY ISN'T EQUIPPED FOR
SUCH A DETAILED BIOANALYSIS.
THE COMPLEX AT PAFFRAN
HAS EVERYTHING WE NEED.
LOOK, IF MY SHIP
IS STILL SEARCHING FOR ME
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
STAY THERE FOREVER.
I HAVE TO GET BACK.
THAT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
WE DON'T EVEN UNDERSTAND
HOW YOU GOT HERE.
THEN MAYBE I CAN FIGURE OUT
A WAY TO GET BACK.
LET ME TAKE A LOOK AT ONE
OF THOSE CENOTAPHS.
THERE'S NO TIME FOR THAT.
WORD ABOUT YOU HAS SPREAD
VERY QUICKLY, HARRY.
NOT ONLY IN THE SCIENTIFIC
WORLD,
BUT IN THE COMMUNITY
AT LARGE.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE
WHO ARE VERY... NERVOUS
ABOUT WHAT YOU REPRESENT.
SOME EVEN SEE YOU AS A THREAT
TO THEIR BELIEFS
ABOUT THE AFTERLIFE.
WE NEED TO TAKE YOU
TO A MORE SECURE LOCATION.
IT'S FOR YOUR OWN PROTECTION.
WAIT!
I'M SORRY, HARRY.
IT'S OUT OF MY CONTROL.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
PREPARING FOR
THE TRANSFERENCE RITUAL.
THIS IS A CEREMONIAL SHROUD
THAT'S BEEN IN MY FAMILY
FOR FIVE GENERATIONS.
SO THEY MAKE YOU WRAP YOURSELF
IN YOUR OWN DEATH SHROUD?
IT'S SOMETHING WE LOOK
FORWARD TO, ACTUALLY.
I REMEMBER
WHEN MY FATHER USED THIS SHROUD
AND HIS FATHER BEFORE HIM.
THE DIFFERENCE IS,
WHEN MY FATHER PUT THIS ON
THERE WAS NO DOUBT IN HIS MIND
ABOUT WHERE HE WAS GOING.
CAN'T YOU JUST BACK OUT?
SAY YOU'VE CHANGED YOUR MIND?
I... HAVE THOUGHT OF JUST
WALKING OUT AND DISAPPEARING.
I HAVE SOME FRIENDS
IN THE CARARIAN MOUNTAINS.
THEY WOULD BE WILLING
TO LET ME STAY WITH THEM.
BUT MY FAMILY
WOULD WORRY ABOUT ME.
THEY'D WONDER
WHAT WAS HAPPENING
IF I WAS ALL RIGHT,
IF I WERE HURT...
NO. EVERYONE'S EXPECTING
A TRANSFERENCE RITUAL
AND I'M GOING TO GIVE THEM ONE.
WHAT IF YOU DID DISAPPEAR
INTO THE MOUNTAINS...
BUT YOUR FAMILY
THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD?
I MEAN, THEY'RE HERE FOR
A TRANSFERENCE RITUAL, RIGHT?
DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT YOU'RE SUGGESTING?
IT'S PERFECT.
THOSE CENOTAPHS SEND YOUR PEOPLE
BACK TO MY DIMENSION
WHICH IS WHERE I WANT TO GO.
VOYAGER'S PROBABLY STILL NEAR
THE ASTEROID SEARCHING FOR ME.
AS SOON AS I APPEAR,
THEY'LL PICK UP MY SIGNAL
AND BEAM ME ABOARD.
AND YOU...
YOU CAN
JUST DISAPPEAR.
YOUR FAMILY WILL
THINK YOU'RE DEAD
AND YOU CAN LIVE
OUT YOUR LIFE
IN THE MOUNTAINS.
HARRY, IF YOU GO
INTO THAT CENOTAPH
AND GO THROUGH
WITH THE TRANSFERENCE RITUAL
YOU'LL DIE.
WELL, IF VOYAGER CAN
BEAM ME ABOARD QUICKLY ENOUGH
OUR DOCTOR SHOULD BE ABLE
TO REVIVE ME.
MEDICINE'S PRETTY ADVANCED
IN OUR CULTURE.
I'VE HEARD OF CASES WHERE PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN DEAD FOR HOURS
AND STILL BEEN BROUGHT
BACK TO LIFE.
BUT IT'S NOT CERTAIN...
NO, IT'S NOT, BUT I THINK THIS
IS MY ONLY CHANCE TO GET HOME.
THE SHROUD HAS TO BE WRAPPED
IN A PARTICULAR WAY.
I'LL SHOW YOU HOW.
BUT WE HAVE TO HURRY.
I'M SCHEDULED FOR TRANSFERENCE
IN LESS THAN AN HOUR.
A PLEASANT TRIP, HATIL.
SAY HELLO TO VAREL AND TOYAN.
I'LL SEE YOU THERE
IN A FEW YEARS.
WE ARE JOINED HERE TODAY
TO BID FAREWELL
TO OUR DEAR FRIEND HATIL GARAN.
WE SALUTE NOT ONLY HIS LIFE,
BUT THE MANNER IN WHICH
HE HAS CHOSEN TO END IT.
HE MAKES A NOBLE SACRIFICE TODAY
THAT HIS FAMILY
MAY HAVE A BETTER TOMORROW.
WE PREPARE TO SEND HIM
ON TO THE NEXT EMANATION
WITH THE FULL KNOWLEDGE
AND FAITH
THAT THE LIFE HE WILL FIND THERE
IS BETTER THAN THE ONE HERE,
THAT HE WILL NO LONGER
BE HAMPERED BY HIS INFIRMITY,
AND THAT HE WILL COME
TO UNDERSTAND THE COSMOS
IN A WAY THAT HE COULD
NEVER HAVE IMAGINED.
GOOD-BYE, HATIL.
I LOVE YOU.
ANOTHER VACUOLE. DECK 15.
THE BODY OF AN ALIEN FEMALE
HAS BEEN LEFT BEHIND.
CHAKOTAY
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM THREE.
LOCK ONTO THE BODY ON DECK 15
AND TRANSPORT IT
TO ONE OF THE ASTEROIDS.
Seska:
Aye, sir.
STATUS ON THE WARP CORE,
LIEUTENANT.
THE DAMPENING FIELD'S
DOWN TO 21 PERCENT.
THE INTERLOCKS WON'T
HOLD MUCH LONGER.
I RECOMMEND
LEAVING, CAPTAIN.
VERY WELL.
MR. PARIS,
BRING US ABOUT.
PREPARE TO
RESUME OUR...
CAPTAIN,
I'M PICKING UP A VACUOLE
FORMING ON DECK 12.
IT DEPOSITED A HUMAN BODY...
Janeway:
HUMAN?
BUT IT'S DEAD.
JANEWAY TO SESKA.
THERE'S A BODY
ON DECK 12.
BEAM IT DIRECTLY
TO SICK BAY.
Seska:
Yes, Captain.
2cc's CORDRAZINE.
( gasping )
Dr. Zimmerman:
RELAX, MR. KIM.
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
YOU'RE ALIVE.
MIND IF I JOIN YOU?
NO, NOT AT ALL.
PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
SO HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
BETTER. I'LL BE READY
FOR DUTY TOMORROW MORNING.
YOU'RE OFF DUTY
FOR THE NEXT TWO DAYS.
CAPTAIN, I'M FINE.
IT'S NOT A REFLECTION
ON YOUR CAPABILITIES, ENSIGN.
I JUST WANT TO GIVE YOU A CHANCE
TO REFLECT ON WHAT'S HAPPENED.
THIS MAY NOT MAKE
MUCH SENSE TO YOU NOW--
A YOUNG MAN
AT THE BEGINNING OF HIS CAREER--
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS YOU LEARN
AS YOU MOVE UP THE RANKS AND GET
A LITTLE OLDER IS THAT...
YOU WISH YOU HAD MORE TIME
IN YOUR YOUTH TO REALLY ABSORB
ALL THE THINGS
THAT HAPPEN TO YOU.
IT GOES BY SO FAST.
IT'S SO EASY TO BECOME JADED,
TO TREAT THE EXTRAORDINARY
LIKE JUST ANOTHER DAY
AT THE OFFICE.
BUT SOMETIMES,
THERE ARE EXPERIENCES
WHICH TRANSCEND ALL THAT.
YOU'VE JUST HAD ONE, MR. KIM,
AND I WANT YOU TO LIVE WITH IT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
WRITE ABOUT IT
IF YOU FEEL LIKE IT.
PAINT...
EXPRESS YOURSELF
IN SOME FASHION.
THE BRIDGE WILL STILL BE THERE
IN TWO DAYS.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I HAVE BEEN A LITTLE PREOCCUPIED
WITH THE EXPERIENCE.
I MEAN, ALL THOSE PEOPLE THINK
THAT THEY KNOW
WHAT HAPPENS AFTER DEATH.
THEY LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
THEY'RE PREPARED FOR IT.
BUT THE TRUTH IS,
NONE OF IT'S REAL.
THEY DON'T HAVE AN AFTERLIFE.
THEY JUST DECAY
INSIDE THOSE ASTEROIDS.
I WOULDN'T BE SO SURE OF THAT
IF I WERE YOU.
THAT NEURAL ENERGY
THEIR BODIES RELEASE--
IT BECOMES PART
OF THE AMBIENT
ELECTROMAGNETIC FIELD
SURROUNDING THE PLANET.
OUR READINGS
ALSO INDICATE
THE ENERGY IS UNUSUALLY DYNAMIC.
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL
OF VARIATION
IN PATTERN COMPLEXITY,
QUANTUM DENSITY...
ARE YOU SAYING YOU THINK
THEY DO HAVE AN AFTERLIFE?
THAT THE ENERGY FIELD
IS WHERE THEY EXIST
AT A HIGHER LEVEL
OF CONSCIOUSNESS
JUST LIKE THEY BELIEVE?
I'M NOT CERTAIN.
BUT I AM CERTAIN ABOUT THIS--
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT DEATH
IS FAR, FAR GREATER
THAN WHAT WE DO KNOW.
SEE YOU IN TWO DAYS, ENSIGN.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.