What?
I've seen that look before.
Ensign Murphy
had better watch out.
I happen to know
that Murphy is seeing
one of the Delaney sisters.
Not since Harry and Tom Paris
made their move.
Harry and
the Delaney sisters?
He would have told me.
I guess there are some things
he keeps to himself.
Harry...
is it true about you
and the Delaney sisters?
Is what true?
Come on, Harry.
There aren't any secrets
on a ship this small.
What have you been
telling people?
Well, we did take that
trip to Venice with them.
KIM:
The holodeck?
You got
to be kidding.
That lasted
all of 15 minutes.
Yeah, you know,
I've been meaning to ask you.
What happened when
you and Jenny Delaney
disappeared
in that gondola?
Nothing.
Harry, we're your friends.
You can tell us.
Nothing.
We... talked.
And then...
I fell over the side.
You fell out of
the gondola?
I think maybe Harry
wasn't quite prepared
for how voracious
Jenny Delaney can be.
I think it's finally
beginning to happen.
Both crews getting along.
That kind of bonding
should improve performance
and maximize efficiency.
Yes, I'm sure it will.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, we're receiving
a distress call
in one of the lower
subspace bands.
I'm on my way.
This is it.
Thanks.
Report, Commander.
The subspace
distress signal's
coming from a vessel
bearing 125 mark 21.
Distance:
200,000 kilometers.
Captain...
sensors indicate five
life-forms aboard.
The vessel is altering
its course to intercept us.
Go to Yellow Alert
and slow to impulse.
Hail them, Mr. Kim.
Aye, Captain.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
starship Voyager.
What is the nature
of your emergency?
We have no emergency.
But you're sending out
a distress call.
Yes, we are.
Why?
Because you are in distress.
I am Gathorel Labin
of the planet Sikaris.
Please, let us welcome you
to our system,
show you the hospitality
of our people.
That's very kind of you...
If I could come aboard
your ship,
I have gifts for you
and a proposal I hope
you will find irresistible.
Mr. Tuvok, make
the necessary arrangements
to receive our guest.
( humming softly )
Ah...
Mr. Labin, it really
isn't necessary
to go to all
of this trouble.
Please, call me Gath.
And I promise you,
I would like nothing better
than to prepare a few of our
newest delicacies for you.
Ah, this will
be perfect.
Uh-uh, Captain, I'm serving
lunch in less than two hours.
We won't be long, Neelix.
This is Mr.--
This is Gath.
He's from Sikaris.
Ooh, Sikaris.
Do you know the planet?
Only stories about their
incredible hospitality.
Tell me, how do
you know about us?
Our people are
very well-traveled.
Some of them have
brought back stories
about the ship
of aliens
from another part
of the galaxy--
People lost and alone,
struggling to find
their way home again.
This is wonderful.
And I decided to
come and meet you,
and offer you respite.
Respite?
A vacation,
if you will.
Get away from the confines
of the ship,
enjoy the beauty
of our landscape,
meet and talk with interesting,
learn-ed people.
And the crew would
certainly welcome
a little shore leave,
Captain.
And I hear the Sikarians
have a huge variety
of edible plants.
If we could
collect some seeds,
we'd expand our selection
significantly.
Sounds like all this
would increase performance
and maximize efficiency.
Don't you think,
Mr. Tuvok?
Indeed.
Well, Gath, looks like
you're getting visitors.
We'll set a course
and follow you in.
I could not be happier.
GATH:
If you see
anything you like,
just let me know.
What is this material?
It's so delicate.
Exquisite, isn't it?
It's the latest import
from Dedestris.
It's spun from
the petals of a flower
that blooms
only in moonlight.
Shall I have
a dress made for you?
It's lovely,
but, no... thank you.
Is it so hard
for you to accept a gift?
All right,
but something small.
Maybe a scarf?
What a curious people
you are.
Tell me,
would it help if I said
that you could have
an entire wardrobe
made from these
beautiful fabrics,
and that it would give
all of us pleasure
to create it for you?
Let's...
start with the scarf.
As you like.
Which cloth do
you prefer, huh?
( tones chiming )
That's beautiful.
Are you a musician?
This isn't a
musical instrument.
It's an atmospheric sensor.
The frequency of the chimes
indicates changes
in weather conditions.
Then it must work
on a principle
of non-linear resonance,
adjusting
to the dynamic variables
in the atmosphere.
That's exactly right.
Are you a scientist?
In a sense.
Can you show me
how to operate it?
I'd be happy to.
First, you have
to initialize
the sub-harmonic mode.
( tones chiming )
( laughs )
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I think this one.
When I see you
wearing that scarf,
my pleasure will be
greater than yours.
Well, I should get back.
But with your permission,
I'd like to start
organizing teams
to gather plants
and seeds.
This is my associate,
Jaret Otel.
You may contact him
to make
any necessary
arrangements.
We'll be glad to assist you
in any way, Captain.
I'll find my officers,
and we'll return
to the ship.
Tonight, we are having
a celebration here.
I hope you and your officers
will be my guests.
We'd be delighted.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48642.5.
The crew is enjoying an evening
on Sikaris.
They are discovering,
to their delight, that reports
of this species' hospitality
have not been exaggerated.
KIM:
...so the whole thing exploded,
and there we were,
70,000 light-years from home,
and no way to get back.
Felt pretty lonely.
That's a very noble story.
Noble?
Mm-hmm. Stories
can be whimsical
or frightening
or-or melancholy
or many other things,
but noble stories
are the ones
that can most
affect our lives.
May I have
your permission
to tell others
this story?
Sure.
It's no secret.
But stories are
an essential part
of every person's being.
I would never share one
without permission.
Go right ahead.
I've got a few others too.
You do?
Come with me.
I know a private place
where you can tell me
all your stories.
Stand close to me.
Alastria.
( chuckles )
Mm...
Where are we?
The woods of Alastria.
My favorite place.
I usually come here
when I want
to spend time alone,
but tonight, it...
it seemed right to bring you.
Now...
tell me your stories.
All of them.
Why is it so much
warmer here?
What is that?
The dawn zephyr.
Dawn? We just got here.
( sighs )
That's... that is
an amazing feeling.
What... what's happening?
The erosene winds--
passion winds...
come just before the dawn.
The erosene
creates euphoria.
I'll say.
Why am I seeing two suns?
Because this is
a binary system.
But your planet
only has one sun.
But Alastria has two.
Eudana...
Hmm?
Where are we?
I told you...
Alastria--
a system far from Sikaris.
How far?
Do you have to ask
all these questions?
Please, it's important.
Alastria is about
two and a half billion times
the distance between
Sikaris and its sun.
That's almost...
40,000 light-years.
Mmm...
Now...
( wind blowing softly )
...feel the breeze.
Um, we have to go back.
It's still night on Sikaris.
We have plenty of time.
No. Um...
we're going back.
And I need you
to tell me everything you know
about that platform
that got us here.
GATH:
And tomorrow night, you must
let me take you to the theater.
Oh, my.
I have lost
all track of time.
My crew has gone.
I'm the last one here.
I hope that's because
you are enjoying yourself.
I am.
KIM:
Captain!
Excuse me for interrupting,
but I've just found out
about something incredible.
Calm down, Ensign.
What is it?
That platform...
it's a transportation device.
Extremely sophisticated.
It operates on the principle
of folding space.
That's something
that's been theorized,
but no one's ever been able
to develop the technology.
Well, these people have.
I've just been
to Alastria and back.
Alastria is 40,000
light-years away.
We call it a
spatial trajector.
We're able to travel
to all the planets
in this quadrant.
How far can it take you?
Alastria is at the outermost
limits of its range.
KIM:
Apparently, it's never been used
to move anything
as large as Voyager,
but as I understand the
principle of space folding,
the size of the object
isn't relevant.
What do you think?
Would it be possible
to modify your technology
so we could use it?
I tried to tell him.
What is it?
We cannot share our technology.
Once it's out of our control,
it might fall into the hands
of those who would abuse it,
and our Canon of Laws
strictly forbids that.
But we wouldn't abuse it.
KIM:
Don't you see
what it would mean to us?
Please, don't make it
more difficult for me.
I don't enjoy denying you this,
but our Canon of
Laws has determined
our entire system
of values.
To break one of its precepts
would undermine
everything we believe in.
I'm sorry, but there can be
no exceptions to the law.
I can't believe
they're not going to help us.
Some kind of hospitality.
40,000 light-years.
Even if that's as
far as we could go,
it would still knock about
four decades off our trip.
And the possibility exists
that we could reconfigure
the matrix at that point
to take us another
30,000 light-years
right into
Federation space.
Since they've already said no,
this kind of thinking is only
going to make you feel worse.
It's the first time
we've been on the other side
of the fence.
What fence?
The one that's made
of binding principles.
We have our own set of rules,
which includes
the Prime Directive.
How many times
have we been in the position
of refusing to interfere
when some kind of disaster
threatened an alien culture?
It's all very well
to say we do it
on the basis of
an enlightened principle,
but how does that feel
to the aliens?
I'm sure many
of them think
the Prime Directive
is a lousy idea.
Even we think so
sometimes.
I know of many times
when Starfleet personnel
have decided
on strong ethical grounds
to ignore it.
Still, there's a reason why
it's Starfleet's
General Order #1.
On the whole, it does
a lot more good than harm.
Captain,
it occurs to me
that we know little
about the Sikarians.
We cannot assume that their
first refusal is unalterable.
It may be that "no" is simply
a prelude to negotiation.
TORRES:
He's right. Maybe they
can be reasoned with.
CHAKOTAY:
Maybe they
want something.
Maybe they'll bargain.
But what do we
have to offer?
They seem to have
everything they need.
Stories.
Stories are an important part
of their culture.
They seem to provide
more than entertainment.
They're kind of
a measuring rod of values
and beliefs.
We have a huge library
in our data banks.
We could offer them
the whole thing.
All the great literature
of dozens of cultures.
What do you think,
Captain?
Would they
be interested?
They just might be.
From what we've
seen of them,
they're a remarkably
pleasure-oriented people.
They might appreciate
a gift of literature.
I'll arrange
to meet with Gath.
As magistrate,
he has the authority
to make this decision.
In the meantime,
I'm going to take a look
at that trajector platform.
Maybe I can figure out
how it works.
You'll do nothing of
the sort, Lieutenant.
( sighs )
If I find
this law is negotiable,
I'll make every attempt
to get the technology,
but until then, we won't do
anything that might violate
their Canon of Laws
as we understand it.
That's all.
What's wrong?
I just hope she gets it.
She will.
Mmm. Exquisite.
And what did you say
you call it?
Pecan pie.
I must have the recipe.
I'd be happy
to share it with you.
Gath... I want you to know
I understand your reluctance
to share your technology
with us.
We have
similar restrictions,
but I wondered,
would it make any difference
if I gave you my word
that we would destroy
the trajector matrix
as soon as
we'd used it?
I know this will upset
you, but I can't.
I understand, and frankly,
I suspected as much,
but I have a proposal
which might allow you
to obey your laws
and still give us
what we want.
Surely you could use
the trajector to send us.
40,000 light-years
would mean
a great deal to us,
and in return, we're prepared
to offer you something
you might enjoy.
Oh!
A full library
of the Federation's
finest literature.
Literature?
Centuries of stories.
New stories
from diverse cultures.
Stories that fire
the imagination.
You certainly know
how to tempt me,
Captain.
It's certainly possible.
I'll have to meet with the other
magistrates to discuss it.
No one has ever made
a request like that.
In the meantime,
I'd like to enjoy
every bite of, uh, this...
how did you call it?
Pecan pie.
( indistinct chatter )
I finished
the maintenance check
on the shock attenuation
cylinders.
They'll have to be replaced
in another 2,000 hours,
but we'll face that problem
when we come to it.
Seska.
Sorry. I wasn't
concentrating.
What did you say?
You looked a million
light-years away.
No.
Only about 70,000.
My brother's birthday
is in four days.
Last year, I promised
I'd meet him on Nivoch
to celebrate
with him.
He'll think
I broke my promise.
That I'm dead.
What are you doing?
I've been thinking.
The folding of space should
leave a sub-space residue.
If we can detect one,
we might be a step closer
to knowing
how the trajector works.
Look at that
neutrino dispersion pattern.
Could that be the result
of space folding?
Maybe. If the device
creates a
neutrino bubble
around whatever's
being trajected.
If that's the case,
we'd need a bubble
big enough for the ship.
Don't worry,
Lieutenant.
I'm with you on this one.
After all,
it doesn't hurt to theorize.
Right, and
hypothetically,
if we could modify
the deflector array
to emit phased neutrinos,
we could create a
big enough bubble.
Let's give it a try.
In theory, of course.
I don't understand.
Why is it so important
I come here now?
You'll see in a minute.
We're here.
Good evening, Ensign.
Thank you for coming.
What's this about?
I asked Eudana
to invite you here
because I was sure you
would respond to her
and because it would
look perfectly natural.
I am prepared to accept
your collection of literature
in exchange
for our trajector technology.
Is that something
you're authorized to do?
Officially, no,
but many people believe
that rules
should be flexible enough
to meet the needs
of the moment.
There is a great desire here
for new stories,
and I want to be the one
to supply them.
So you'd stand to benefit
from this arrangement, right?
We would both benefit.
I would gain prestige,
and you would gain
40,000 light-years
in your journey home,
possibly more.
This is it, Ensign,
the matrix of
the trajector.
Captain Janeway
has asked the magistrate
to send us 40,000 light-years.
He won't.
He never had any intention
of helping you leave here.
EUDANA:
Jaret is right.
I know how much
it means to you to get home.
Please,
listen to him.
You must believe me
when I tell you
this is the only way
you will make that journey.
Consider my offer.
I'm sure you will decide
it is a fair one.
I don't know what to do.
I know we'd all like to get
that much closer to home,
but I don't think
Captain Janeway
is going to go for getting
the technology like that.
Maybe she will.
After all,
it's a Sikarian
who's making the offer.
But it's not aboveboard.
The Captain
is only going to deal
with an official
representative.
Bridge to Ensign Kim.
The Captain can see you now.
Just tell her
everything you know.
Let her take it from there.
Right.
I'll walk you partway.
I'm headed for bed.
( sighs )
Somehow... I have
a bad feeling about this.
It's just not going
to work out.
Don't you think
that's up to us?
What does that mean?
It means that
we can sit here
and let someone make
the decision for us,
or we can take matters
into our own hands.
We've been offered
the grand prize.
All we have to do is
step up and claim it.
Take the technology?
Without permission?
Since when
do you talk like that?
Do you think permission
is more important
than getting us halfway home?
The Captain is so infatuated
with the Sikarian magistrate,
she can't
think straight.
We can't trust
that she's going to make
the best decision for all of us.
If we do this,
we'll need to use Engineering
to configure the matrix.
It will be a lot easier
if we knew
we could count on you.
Seska, I am
a Senior Officer now.
I have responsibilities.
And the main responsibility
for everyone on this ship
is to try to find a way home.
Captain Janeway made that clear
from the beginning.
That's our primary mission.
Just think about it.
That's all.
Did Jaret explain what he meant
when he said
Gath had no intention
of helping us leave?
No. He just made it clear
that our only choice
was to get the trajector
technology from him.
He may simply want us to believe
that so we would deal with him.
Possibly...
but somehow,
I suspect he's right.
Thank you for coming to me
with this, Ensign.
It may muddy
the situation somewhat,
but it helps me
force the issue.
Dismissed.
Good night, Captain. Lieutenant.
Oh, Tuvok,
what do I do now?
You would seem to
have two options.
Continue to negotiate
with a man
who may have
a hidden agenda,
or deal with a man
who is willing to
defy his own laws.
Not very pretty choices.
At least if you
deal with Jaret,
it is his law that
is being compromised,
not ours.
But does that matter?
I told the crew
when we started this journey
that we'd be a Starfleet crew,
behaving as Starfleet
would expect us to.
That means there's a certain
standard I have to uphold.
Principles, principles.
That's what it comes down to.
Do I compromise
my almighty principles?
But how do I not compromise them
if it involves a chance
to get the crew
more than halfway home?
How do I tell them...
my principles are so important
I would deny them
that opportunity?
I believe
the first thing you must do
is determine whether or not
Gath is willing to use
the trajector to help us.
If that possibility
exists at all,
you must explore it.
You're right.
Thank you, Tuvok.
JANEWAY:
Have you spoken with
the other magistrates
about using
the trajector?
Actually, I haven't.
Some of them
are traveling now,
but I assure you
I will do it.
Oh, I've already seen
all those.
It's becoming a matter
of some urgency.
Oh. Why?
We've imposed on you
for long enough.
Not true.
We welcome you
for as long as you can stay,
and I hope that's
a very long time indeed.
My crew is eager to
continue our journey.
Once they realized
the trajector might bring
us 40,000 light-years
closer to home...
Why are you so consumed
with this desire to get home?
I find it difficult
to understand.
Home... is home.
It's where we belong.
Couldn't you create
a new home here with us?
Can you imagine
a more delightful place to live
where you could pass your time
extracting pleasure
from every moment?
I promise you,
you and I have many
such moments to explore.
Yes, but for how long?
I've seen how quickly
you get tired of
your pleasures.
All that interests you
is what's new
and unexplored.
After a day or two,
it becomes commonplace.
Yes...
We prefer
permanence...
the reward
of relationships that endure
and grow deeper
with the passing of time.
You would lose those notions
if you stayed with us.
You may be right,
and that's why we have to leave.
We have offered you
nothing but hospitality.
Is this how you repay us,
with an attack on our beliefs?
I'm sorry.
I was just trying to illustrate
the differences between us.
I don't enjoy
being judged like this.
It's very upsetting.
Not at all pleasurable.
That's all you really
care about, isn't it?
Your pleasure.
All your hospitality,
your graciousness--
it was never about
giving us pleasure.
It's all been
to gratify yourselves.
We're nothing more than
the latest novelty.
You're hostile and vicious.
You would infect
the joyousness of our lives.
You must leave immediately.
You never had any intention
of helping us, did you?
Of course I did.
I did everything in my power
to persuade you to stay here.
Janeway to Voyager.
One to beam up.
Cancel all shore leave
and recall the away teams.
We've been asked to leave.
Aye, Captain.
I assume that means Gath
will not be assisting us.
I don't think he ever had
any intention of helping us.
He just...
strung us along.
Are you considering
Jaret's offer?
Oh, I wish I could...
but I can't.
Captain, it'll take hours
to get everyone up.
We've got crew members scattered
throughout both hemispheres.
Get them back as quickly
as you can, Commander.
I think we've
overextended our stay here.
I'll be in my ready room.
SESKA:
I've downloaded
the Federation library.
It's all on these chips.
We know the man to contact.
He wants the library,
and he doesn't care
who gives it to him.
We're under orders...
B'Elanna, right now
our people are still
fighting Cardassians,
dying for our cause.
Settlers in
the Demilitarized Zone
are still under attack.
We made a promise, B'Elanna,
that we'd all stick together
until the Zone was safe,
and I intend
to keep that promise.
I have a wife
and two little boys.
I don't want them to grow up
without a father.
I'd do anything to prevent that.
We're not
the only ones.
Everyone wants
to get back.
They're just waiting
for someone to act.
I've been working
on the theory that the trajector
operates within
a neutrino envelope.
If that's true,
I think we can use it
as many times
as we need
until we're all the way home.
Just think... by tomorrow,
we could be there.
All right.
Let's do it.
With shore leave canceled,
are we able to get to
the surface undetected?
We'll have to override
the security lockout,
but that shouldn't
be a problem.
It's not accepting
my security code.
Reinitialize
the lockout buffers.
I did.
It's not working.
Someone's altered
the security subroutine.
Why would anyone do that?
Never mind. Beam me down.
Are you crazy?!
Security will find you out
before you get there.
I altered
the security subroutines.
Any attempt to override
the lockout
would have alerted me
to your presence here.
Is this
Voyager's library
which you intended to trade
for the trajector technology?
Yes.
When I attempted
to download it,
I noticed it had
already been accessed.
You were going
to download it?
I will make the exchange
with Jaret Otel.
Return to your stations.
Do what you can
to prepare the ship
for the matrix.
Energize.
Mr. Tuvok is
on the surface now, Captain.
He says the remaining
away teams
should be on board
within 15 minutes.
Are all the food
supplies secured?
Aye, Captain. As soon as
the last of the crew gets back,
we'll be ready
to leave.
Bridge to Engineering.
Torres here.
We'll be leaving orbit
within minutes.
Ready all propulsion systems.
We're ready now, Captain.
Where's Tuvok?
He'll be here.
We certainly won't leave
without him.
Well, what's keeping him?
Calm down.
You're going to draw
attention to yourself.
Do not attempt
to activate the device
until I've spoken
to Captain Janeway.
What are you doing?
He said
not to activate it.
I'm not.
I'm just going to try
the interface simulation.
We don't even know
if it will interface.
We can give ourselves
a head start by testing it now.
All right.
But just a simulation.
It's working.
I was right.
It operates within
a neutrino envelope.
The trajector field is bigger
than anything we've created
by ten orders
of magnitude.
To get a field that size,
you'd need an amplifier
as big as a planet.
I don't understand.
How do they get that
kind of amplification?
I'll show you.
Sikaris has a mantle
of tetrahedral quartz
20 kilometers thick.
The crystalline structure
of the mantle
serves to focus and amplify
the trajector field.
If that's how
the power transfer occurs,
then once we leave orbit,
we lose the ability to traject.
We don't have time to test it.
We'll have to try it now
or forget it.
Do it.
If there are
any compatibility problems--
Then we can abort.
This is our only chance.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Engineering.
Torres here.
We're ready to leave orbit.
Thrusters on-line.
Aye, Captain.
We have to do something.
( beeping )
Mr. Paris,
take us out of orbit.
4,000 kph.
Aye, Captain.
There's no response.
Thrusters are off line.
Janeway to Engineering.
What's going on, Lieutenant?
We've got a phase variance
in plasma conduit 3.
I'll have to check it out before
we can engage thrusters.
When did this problem show up?
Just now, Captain.
It's only a slight variance.
I'll have it fixed in a minute.
Keep me advised.
All right.
The matrix is activating.
The trajector field is forming.
CAREY:
And it's amplifying.
Look how fast it's expanding.
That's the effect
of the quartz mantle.
We're nearly
at full field strength.
This is going to work.
( alarm sounding )
What is it?
The plasma manifold
is becoming unstable.
I can compensate for that.
CAREY:
The manifold is being bombarded
by anti-neutrinos
from the trajector field.
Anti-neutrinos?
The must be the catalyst
for the space folding process.
It's not working.
I can't compensate
for the instability.
CAREY:
There's no way to compensate for
a field that size.
( deep thud )
Captain, I'm showing
an unstable plasma manifold.
We're headed for a breach.
Bridge to Torres.
What's happening?
We're reading
a warp core breach up here.
We're on it, Captain.
No time to talk.
Shut down the matrix!
I can't!
It's not responding!
CAREY:
It's fused!
Plasma temperature
at 43 million Kelvin!
Carey, get everybody out!
All right, people, let's go!
Right now!
Move it out!
Move out! Come on!
Let's go! Right now!
Let's go, come on!
Move it out! Fast!
Right now!
Keep moving!
I can't unlock it.
The command matrix is sealed.
Plasma temperature
at 50 million Kelvin!
Anti-neutrino
bombardment has stopped.
Plasma temperature
dropping.
We didn't anticipate
anti-neutrinos.
The trajector could
never be compatible
with Federation technology.
I'll start erasing
the sensor logs.
We can blame it
on the phase discrepancy.
No.
We're not going
to cover this up.
Are you crazy?
We don't have
to take the blame for this.
But we're going to.
We disobeyed orders,
gambling it would pay off.
It didn't.
And now we just can't pretend
like nothing happened.
I don't understand.
There's no need for this.
I'm sorry
if you don't get it, Seska,
but it has something
to do with, um...
with being able
to live with yourself.
That doesn't sound like you.
You've changed.
If that's true...
I take it as a compliment.
I take full responsibility
for what happened.
There were others involved,
but I was the Senior Officer,
and the culpability
is mine.
Lieutenant Torres is not
precisely correct, Captain.
She was not
the Senior Officer involved.
I was.
You?
It was I who made the exchange.
The Federation library
for the trajector matrix.
I will deal with you
in a moment.
I don't have the luxury
of throwing you in the brig
for the rest of this voyage.
I need you.
I need every person
on this ship.
But I want you to know
how very deeply
you have disappointed me.
If there are
any further transgressions,
even a minor one...
you will no longer
be an officer on this crew.
Is that clear?
Yes, ma'am.
Dismissed.
I don't even know
where to start.
I want you
to explain to me
how you, of all people,
could be involved in this.
It is quite simple, Captain.
You have made it clear
on many occasions
that your highest goal
for the crew
is to get them home.
But in this instance,
your standards
would not allow you
to violate
Sikarian law.
Someone had to spare you
the ethical dilemma.
I was the logical choice,
and so I chose to act.
You did it for me...
because you knew I couldn't.
I accept the consequences
of my actions.
I expect to lose my commission
and to be court-martialed
when we return
to Federation space.
You are one of
my most valued officers...
and you are my friend.
It is vital that
you understand me here.
I need you.
But I also need to know
that I can count on you.
You are my counsel,
the one I turn to when I need
my moral compass checked.
We have forged
this relationship for years,
and I depend on it.
I realize you made
a sacrifice for me...
but it's not one
I would have allowed you
to make.
You can use logic
to justify almost anything.
That's its power...
and its flaw.
From now on...
bring your logic to me.
Don't act on it behind my back.
You have my word.
My logic was not in error...
but I was.
Dismissed.