Commander!
Look at this.
I think they're
some kind of apple.
There are trees
filled with them
as far as the eye can see
just over that ridge.
Kaylos. Ah.
Aren't they gorgeous?
One bite'll kill you.
Puff you up like a vakolfish.
Yeah, first
your windpipe
( gasping )
swells...
and just when you think
you're going to die
of suffocation...
Ow! Oh, you get a sharp pain
in your knees,
which begins to work
its way right up to...
I think we get
the picture.
Sorry, Mr. Carey.
Just remember the
old trader's axiom:
Never judge a
fruit by its skin.
On the other hand,
huh, take a bite.
What is it?
A leola root.
You expect us to eat this?
This is the reason
I brought you here, Commander.
There's no better source
of vitamins and minerals
in the Quadrant
than in this,
this ugly little root.
I'd find the second-best source
acceptable if it tasted better.
You humans!
You're not used to
roughing it, are you?
Well, take it
from one who knows.
The day may come
when you'll relish
every last crunch
of leola.
Stewed for a few hours
in a light herbal broth,
ah, you won't even notice
the mildew.
Captain, I don't
think we're alone.
Mr. Tuvok, run a lateral
EM scan for me,
coordinates 81
mark 40.
Running scan.
What do you see, Mr. Paris?
It's like a reflection.
Something in low orbit.
When it moves into
a certain angle from the sun...
He's correct. I am picking up
an ionization trail.
There is another ship in orbit.
Using some kind
of cloaking device?
It's not a cloaking device
as we know it, Captain.
I cannot say for certain
what it is,
but the ship does employ
some kind of masking circuitry
that has affected our sensors.
Voyager to away team.
CHAKOTAY: Go ahead, Captain.
Any unexpected life signs down
there, Commander?
Nothing but bloodworms.
Neelix wants to bring
some back for a tartar
he wants to make. I'm trying
to talk him out of it.
We're picking up an
unidentified ship in low orbit.
Collect your teams,
and prepare to transport back
while we investigate.
Acknowledged.
Chakotay out.
All units, report to transport
site A immediately.
Captain, I believe
a polaron burst
may give us visual contact.
Do it.
Kazon.
The hull design does conform
to known specifications
of the Kazon-Nistrim sect.
Voyager to away teams. Return
to the ship immediately.
Acknowledged, Captain.
Transporter Room, get ready
to begin on my command.
Where is
Ensign Seska?
Chakotay to Seska.
Transporter Room,
can you locate
Ensign Seska's
combadge signal?
Negative, Commander.
I'm not reading any sign of her.
She was picking berries
with our group,
over by the hillside.
There were caves nearby.
If she went inside one,
it might be blocking
her combadge signal.
The rest of you get
back to the ship.
I'm going
to look for her.
Oh, thank
the Prophets!
What are you
doing here?
Mushrooms. I saw them growing
by the mouth of the cave.
I wanted to teach Neelix
how to make your favorite soup.
I appreciate
the thought,
but we've got
to get out of here.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48658.2.
We successfully left orbit
without further interference
from the Kazon.
Commander Chakotay was injured,
but is recovering
from his wounds.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I didn't think
I'd make it.
Feeling better?
Yeah. What have
you got there?
Real food.
You got Neelix to make
some mushroom soup.
Are you kidding?
The man wanted
to stretch the mushrooms
with just a little...
leola root.
Leola root.
We got into
this tug of war
with the bag of mushrooms
in the middle.
It was the most ludicrous thing
you've ever seen.
Tuvok and Kes broke us up,
and then Neelix
threw me out of his kitchen.
So, how did you...?
Mm, strictly a Maquis operation.
Hmm!
First, we arranged
for a little morale crisis.
A couple of our people
suddenly came down
with severe homesickness.
Neelix, our devoted
morale officer,
responded to the call
and came in to cheer them up,
and while they were
all singing Rakan folk songs,
Jackson and I
broke into the kitchen.
You looted the
food reserves?
Well, if he's not going
to give us a decent meal...
I can't believe you did this.
Well, it's not like
we're hiding anything.
I did bring soup straight
to the First Officer, didn't I?
Thanks for including me
in a criminal conspiracy.
Does he know
about this yet?
Well, the morale crisis ended
a few minutes ago, so I'd say...
Neelix to Chakotay.
...that he probably does.
Go ahead, Neelix.
I'd like to report a crime.
Someone has broken into
my kitchen and stolen food--
Taken food out of the mouths
of their crewmates.
I know.
It was that Seska, wasn't it?
I promise you everyone involved
will be disciplined.
If you'd like my recommendations
for punishment...
Thank you.
I'll handle that.
Chakotay out.
Replicator privileges
revoked for two days.
Everyone, including me.
They're not going to do it.
Then I'll personally put them in
the Brig.
You'd put me in the Brig?
After all we've
been through?
The soup was worth losing
the replicator privileges
for two days. Admit it.
That's not the point.
I get the point.
Can we make up now?
Who else knows how to make
your favorite soup like I do?
No one...
but we agreed
a long time ago,
this wouldn't work.
Look around, Chakotay.
There aren't that many
potential mates out here.
Of course, if you're
not interested...
I have had my eye
on young Ensign Kim.
Janeway to all senior officers.
Please report to the bridge.
MALE:
We require help... immediately!
Anyone who can hear
this message, please help!
Long-range scanners
picked up the distress signal
three minutes ago.
TUVOK:
The ship's dimensions
are identical
to the vessel
we encountered at the planet.
It is a Kazon-Nistrim
ship, Captain.
Captain, this may be a trap.
The Kazon-Nistrim is one
of the most violent sects
in the entire Kazon Collective.
We need immediate assistance!
We have lost
all bridge operations.
Barely able to function.
Please... assist!
Mr. Kim, can you determine
if this ship
has sustained genuine damage?
There are fluctuating
nucleonic patterns.
It might indicate a
reactor breakdown on board.
Mr. Paris, run an extended
scanner sequence
to identify
any other Kazon ships
that might be in the area.
( console beeping )
Nothing showing up, Captain.
Maintain scans
and set a heading to intercept.
PARIS:
New heading entered.
I take your warning
seriously, Neelix,
and will act
with caution,
but if we can
help, we should.
Besides,
this may be
an opportunity
to make a friend,
and out here,
we can use all the friends
we can get.
TORRES:
What could do something like
this?
I'm showing high levels
of nucleonic radiation.
It seems to be isolated
in that area.
It is likely
that the ship's
automatic containment
systems were activated
when the radiation
entered the bridge.
We should be safe
as long as we stay
on this side
of the force field.
Someone's alive over here.
( groaning )
CHAKOTAY:
Away team to Voyager.
We've got a single male Kazon
alive on the bridge.
Transport him
directly to sick bay.
Energizing.
It appears the explosion
emanated from this console.
Something look a little odd
about it to you?
The structural pattern
does not conform
to the rest of the bridge.
There's something else
strange about it.
The residue has a .41 percent
trace of a neosorium composite,
and I don't know anyone
who uses neosorium technology,
except for
the Federation.
So how did it get into
the hands of the Kazon?
Incredible.
Somehow, virtually every cell
in his body has been altered.
Altered?
His cells
have mutated,
or they've been fused
with inorganic matter.
I can't make heads or tails
of it. Look at this.
His blood cells have bonded
with metallic nuclei.
The crew members
closest to the explosion
were virtually melded with
huge pieces of metal fragments.
He was luckier
than the others.
That remains
to be seen.
I'm going to have to do
a complete pyrocyte replacement
if we're going
to keep him alive.
We'd better hope there are
compatible donors on board.
I'll run a cytological
screening of the crew.
We'll let you
know the results
as soon as we can.
Captain, there was an
apparent Federation signature
to the explosion.
What?
It looked like
they were trying to install
some new technology
that detonated.
You're saying
they have some kind
of Federation weapon
on board?
A console on the bridge
was the source of the explosion.
We're not sure
what its function was,
and it's going
to be hard to get to.
We can't
transport it out?
Not with those levels
of nucleonic radiation.
The transporter beam
would disperse
the moment it hit
the irradiated cabin.
How could they possibly
have Federation technology?
There are only
three alternatives
I can discern
at this time.
One: It is not
Federation technology at all,
but something
similar.
Bridge.
Two:
Another Federation starship
may have been brought
to the Delta Quadrant
prior to our arrival,
and they interacted
with the Kazon-Nistrim.
Were there any other
reports of missing starships?
Not to my knowledge.
Three: Someone
from this ship
has covertly given technology
to the Kazon.
Computer,
hold turbolift.
I don't like number three at
all, Tuvok.
Nevertheless, it is the most
probable explanation.
It may not
be a coincidence
that the Kazon ship
we encountered at the planet
was able to deceive
our sensors.
Perhaps someone transmitted
instructions to them
before we arrived.
( sighs )
I want you to personally
go through the
transmission logs, Tuvok.
Compare them to
the actual telemetry.
See if there's any
evidence of prior contact
with the Kazon.
Who would have had a chance
to meet with them
while you were on the surface?
A dozen people.
We were scattered
all over the area.
You did discover Ensign Seska
in proximity to them.
Seska almost killed me
because she thought
I was Kazon.
She wouldn't do
something like this.
Nevertheless, I urge you
to regard her with caution
for the time being.
Why would anyone
on this ship betray us?
We're all in this together.
We need to retrieve that console
and get some answers
before the rumors
get out of hand.
Computer, resume.
Releasing the force field
isn't an option.
That would just allow the
radiation into the whole cabin.
We could generate
a localized subspace bubble
to get past
the force field.
One minor
subspace disruption
and you're dead.
It's too risky.
I'd be willing
to risk it.
We could use an expander
to manipulate
the containment field.
Manipulate it how?
Move it out of the way.
Rotate the field,
and the radiation
trapped inside it
away from the console.
Once it's clear,
we have access.
How long will it take
to set this up?
We, uh, we should be able to
make an attempt by tomorrow.
I want it ready
by the end of the day.
No, Captain.
When I say tomorrow,
I mean tomorrow.
I don't exaggerate.
Tomorrow is the best I can do.
Understood, Lieutenant.
All right... we'll begin
on the Kazon bridge.
Carey, Nicoletti, Seska.
No. I want Ensign Seska
to coordinate the operation
from our bridge.
Okay, Henard,
you're with us.
Dismissed.
What was that all about?
What?
Oh, you know
what I'm talking about.
There's nothing important to do
on the bridge.
I disagree. We need someone
up there--
What the hell
is going on?
There's some concern
about you.
What kind of concern?
Concern because I found you
near the Kazon on the planet.
Oh, I see.
So now I'm a traitor.
I sell technology to the enemy?
I don't believe that.
No, you just take me off
my assignment.
I'm trying to take you out of
harm's way to protect you.
This is your idea
of protection?
You might as well
point a finger at me
in front of the entire crew.
You don't assign someone
you don't trust to the bridge.
Look, I'm sorry,
but if something goes wrong
over there, I don't want you
anywhere near it.
Thanks for
your concern.
How is he?
Not very good.
We need to completely
replace his blood.
Will he regain
consciousness?
I'm not sure.
Even if he does, there's no way
to predict
what kind of brain
damage there might be.
He's the only one
who really knows
what happened
on that ship, Doctor.
The only one
who can tell them
I had nothing
to do with it.
You? I don't
understand.
Would you call me
right away if he wakes up?
All right.
Ensign...
did you ever come in
to leave a blood
sample on file?
No. I never got around to it.
Why?
I've been running a crew
compatibility analysis,
and your file
never came up.
My blood won't help you.
I had a childhood disease
that infected it.
I was warned never to donate
blood for a transfusion.
All the more reason we should
have your blood on file.
I will.
Right now, I have something
more important to take care of.
Someone did make
an unauthorized transmission.
And whoever it was was an expert
at covering their tracks.
The signal was masked by a test
of the dorsal emitters
that we conducted
a week ago.
Who was working
on that test?
Only the whole Engineering crew.
We're trying to trace
the station where the signal
originated.
Again, the perpetrator
was skilled enough
to make the tracking process
extremely difficult for us.
It's like working backwards
through a maze of circuits.
We keep bumping
into dead ends.
Paris to Captain Janeway.
Please report to the bridge.
Captain, another Kazon ship
is approaching,
trying to hail
the disabled ship.
They're not within
visual range yet.
Perhaps someone else
picked up the distress call.
What's their ETA?
At their current speed,
four hours, 20 minutes.
Should I tell them we're here?
If we know about them,
it's a good bet
they know about us.
We don't have anything good
to tell them.
I think we'll wait.
Captain, I'm showing
an unauthorized autosequence
in Transporter Room 2. Someone's
left Voyager.
Computer, identify who just
beamed off the ship
from Transporter Room 2.
Ensign Seska.
Chakotay to Seska.
I really don't have time
to talk to you right now,
Chakotay.
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Retrieving the console, my way.
I want you back
on this ship, and I mean now.
The Captain said she wanted
the console today.
Carey's plan
couldn't do it in time,
but mine can.
Captain, it is conceivable
that she has gone
to the Kazon ship
to destroy evidence
that might implicate her.
She's gone back to the Kazon
ship to prove herself to us.
Can't you see that?
I've got a lock on her, Captain.
Do you want me
to transport her back?
If we try to beam her out
while she's
manipulating subspace,
we might kill her.
( screaming )
Chakotay to Seska.
Seska, respond.
Get her out of there!
Send her to sick bay.
Energizing.
Prep three ccs kelotane.
I'll need a dermal regenerator.
Run a full blood scan.
( moaning )
Have a seat, Mr. Carey.
How have things been going
for you in engineering?
Fine.
Why, is there a problem?
You getting along all right
with Lieutenant Torres?
I think we've settled
our differences.
She was promoted to Chief
Engineer over you, Lieutenant.
That might be difficult
for someone in your position
to accept.
Captain, I accepted
your decision,
and I've worked as hard as I can
to make myself a valuable member
of Lieutenant Torres' team.
I can't believe
she'd have any complaints
about my performance.
She doesn't.
Then what am I doing here?
Lieutenant,
have you had any contact
with the Kazon-Nistrim
since we arrived
in the Delta Quadrant?
What?!
Y-You mean, me personally?
No. Of course not.
You were out of contact
for almost an hour
on the planet
where we encountered the Kazon.
You mean, when I was picking
those poison apples?
What about before
we arrived at the planet?
Did you have any reason
to signal a Kazon-Nistrim ship?
No.
Nevertheless,
a signal was sent to the Kazon
from your station in Engineering
during our
dorsal emitter test last week.
My station?
Were you not in Engineering
at that time?
Well, yes, I was, but...
you know how it is down there
during a systems analysis.
Did you see anyone else
at your station?
Honestly, I don't remember.
Maybe you should ask Seska.
Why Seska?
Everybody knows she was found
in the cave with the Kazon.
Look, I'm not saying
she did anything wrong,
but I didn't either.
I'd like to believe you,
Mr. Carey,
but somebody did contact
the Kazon,
and until we know who,
I'm going to have
to restrict you to quarters.
What do you think?
He had the motive
and the opportunity.
He's also had a distinguished
Starfleet career.
Seska spent most of
the last two years
as an enemy
of the Federation.
So have I.
KIM:
Captain, we're being hailed
by the approaching Kazon ship.
How soon will they be here?
Four minutes.
I wish we had something
more definitive to tell them.
Open a channel.
I am Kathryn Janeway,
Captain of the Federation
starship Voyager.
My name is Culluh,
First Maje of the Kazon-Nistrim.
What have you done to our ship?
We responded to a call for help.
Unfortunately, by the time
we were able to respond,
all but one of the crew
were dead.
I would like to speak
to the survivor.
He hasn't
regained consciousness.
We have him in our sick bay.
We'd be happy to beam you aboard
so you can see him.
You will prepare for my arrival.
Friendly sort.
DOCTOR:
Ah, Captain,
I'm glad you're here.
I was just about
to call you.
Doctor, this is
First Maje Culluh,
of the Kazon-Nistrim.
Could you give us
the latest condition report
on your Kazon patient?
Well, the good news is, we've
been able to stabilize him.
We had to completely
replace his blood.
Replace his blood?
With what?
The blood of volunteers
from our crew.
They saved his life.
His own blood cells
were killing him.
They were changed
by the accident on his ship.
Changed in what manner?
We haven't been able
to determine that yet.
We've been
working on a plan
to access the source
of the explosion,
which should answer
a lot of the questions.
That will no longer
be necessary.
We will take the damaged vessel
to our port for inspection.
I'm afraid I can't allow you
to do that just yet.
And what gives you the right
to interfere in our affairs?
There was a trace
of a Federation compound
in the remains
of the explosion.
We have reason to believe
that someone on board this ship
gave technology
to your people.
Until we have a better
explanation of what occurred,
I can't release
that ship to you.
That is not acceptable.
It will have to be.
Your unique technologies
make you brave, Captain,
but you have only one ship.
In less than a day,
there will be four Kazon vessels
off your bow.
Perhaps by then we'll have
the answers we need.
You will leave us with him.
I assume they'll want to
take him back to their ship.
I'd rather not let them
do it just yet,
in case
he regains consciousness.
There are a lot of questions
he can answer.
Can I tell them
it's not safe to move him?
It will be the truth.
Good.
( steady tone sounds )
He's dead.
Get off this ship.
There was some kind
of nerve toxin
in that needle.
He died instantly.
Captain, may we talk to you
in my office?
It's about Seska.
Complications?
I was analyzing
her blood chemistry
to try to locate
a compatible donor.
But when I got the results,
her blood was lacking
all the common
Bajoran blood factors.
Meaning?
The only conclusion
we can reach
is that she is not,
in fact, Bajoran.
It appears Seska has been
genetically altered.
My suspicion is she
was born Cardassian.
You're asking me to believe
she's a Cardassian agent
who infiltrated the Maquis?
Starfleet Security has
documented several incidents
in which Cardassians
have used cosmetic alterations
for the purpose
of infiltrating an enemy.
This is crazy.
This is just impossible.
The Doctor has informed us
that there is no other
plausible explanation for the
medical anomalies, Commander.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to hear her explanation
before we dismiss it.
Has she been told?
No.
I'd like to be the one
who questions her.
I suggest we wait
until we retrieve the console.
Janeway to Torres.
Yes, Captain.
Your status.
We are finished
with the computer simulations.
Everything looks okay.
We're ready to beam over.
Good. Then let's get started.
Janeway out.
You were working for her,
Seska was working for them.
Was anyone on board
that ship working for me?
The Kazon ship
is hailing us.
Open a channel.
On screen.
Our sensors show that you are
trespassing on our vessel.
As I've already informed you,
we're attempting
to retrieve the console
that caused this explosion.
If you attempt to remove
anything from our ship,
it will be considered
an act of war.
You know,
I'm really easy
to get along with
most of the time...
but I don't like bullies,
and I don't like threats,
and I don't like you, Culluh.
You can try and stop us
from getting to the truth,
but I promise you, if you do,
I will respond with
all the "unique" technologies
at my command.
Janeway out.
Their weapons systems
are standing down.
They do not appear to be posing
a threat to us at this time.
At least not until
reinforcements get here.
Janeway to away team.
TORRES: Yes, Captain?
I don't want to rush you,
Lieutenant, but--
We're finished, Captain.
I beg your pardon?
Decontamination
went exactly as planned.
The console has been transported
to Engineering,
and we're on our way back now.
Acknowledged.
Well done, away team.
We'll meet you
in Engineering.
Of all the things to die for.
It's a food
replicator...
or at least
it was trying to be.
We may take replicators
for granted,
but imagine what it would mean
to a culture that doesn't have
this technology.
They didn't use a thick enough
interior shield casing.
Once the nucleonic radiation
leaked out,
a cascade reaction
was inevitable.
Can you tell if any part of
the console came from our ship?
There's no doubt about it,
Captain.
The pattern buffer relays
are clearly composed
of bioneural fibers.
No other Federation ship
would have them.
Somebody on board Voyager
gave them what they needed.
I guess they just didn't know
what to do with it.
I want a complete report
on everything we've found
so I can share it
with our Kazon friends.
We've recovered
the console.
It's a replicator
constructed with materials
from Voyager.
I suppose now everyone thinks
I went over there
to destroy the evidence.
Did you?
I was only trying
to show everyone--
Show you...
You really think I had something
to do with this, don't you?
To be honest,
I'm not sure anymore.
I'm not sure of
a lot of things.
Then why don't you go talk
to your animal guide
and figure it all out?
I plan to.
Good. Get back to me when you
do.
You know, it's funny...
I've been thinking
about what's been real
and what's
not been real.
What is this about?
What's wrong with you?
Talk to me, Chakotay.
You owe me that much.
What would you say
I owed to a Cardassian
who infiltrated my crew?
What are you talking about?
Isn't that why
you never got around
to a blood analysis
when we came on board?
I didn't get around to it
because I didn't
get around to it.
Turns out your
blood is missing
all the common
Bajoran blood factors.
It's a side effect
of Orkett's disease.
Ask your doctor.
Orkett's disease?
A childhood virus that swept
through the Bajoran work camps
during the Occupation.
Thousands of children
didn't survive.
I did, thanks to
a bone marrow transplant
from a sympathetic
Cardassian woman.
Her name was Kattell.
When we get home,
you can ask her yourself.
You must think I'm horrible.
Do you think I gave you my...
my heart to get
your Maquis secrets?
I was starting to wonder.
Let me tell you something...
your secrets
weren't good enough.
They wouldn't have been worth
the trouble
for a Cardassian agent.
I had only one agenda
with you, Chakotay,
and I never kept it secret.
So you believe in me again?
I want to.
Good, because I want
to go back to work.
Let's not rush things.
No, I'm going stir-crazy
in here.
You're going to have
to stay confined,
at least until we find out
exactly where the
replicator components
were taken from.
Well, what'll that tell you?
There might be evidence
of who took them.
Oh, you don't think
whoever did this
is foolish enough to log in
using their own name?
Chief Inspector Tuvok
leaves no stone unturned.
I'll tell the Captain
what you told me.
Somehow, we'll try
to clear this up soon.
She said a Cardassian
bone marrow transplant
saved her life as a child.
Did you set our
plan in motion?
I gave Lieutenant Carey
the same information.
Now all we can do is wait
and hope someone takes the bait.
Gin.
I never knew Vulcans had such
a talent for cards.
It is simply a matter
of logical discards,
which give a false impression
of my own requirements
and deny the needed cards
to your hand.
I believe that's
94 points to me.
If you ever need a sponsor
in a gin tournament,
let me know.
We're picking up
two more Kazon warships,
about six hours away.
We're not going to be able
to stay here much--
( console beeping )
That sounds like
a nibble to me.
Someone is accessing
the inventory database.
And they're going straight to
the missing replicator
materials.
Should we start
the trace now?
Negative.
It might alert them.
They're entering data.
Intriguing.
It appears as though they're
trying to place evidence
at the scene of the crime
to indicate the guilty party.
They're entering
an encrypted security code
into the materials
requisition file.
Which would suggest
they're hiding it,
but not very well.
Anybody know whose security code
that belongs to?
I do.
It's Seska's.
Then it has to be Carey.
Carey is trying to point
the finger at Seska.
Chakotay...
is anything wrong?
It's over. We know who gave
the technology to the Kazon.
Who?
You did.
Look, I don't know what evidence
you think you've found, but...
We found the evidence
you put there for us to find.
Your own security code.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
We already knew where the stolen
materials had been taken from
before I met with you.
We were monitoring
the inventory manifest,
hoping either you or Carey
would try to cover your tracks.
Hell of a way for me
to cover my tracks,
putting in my own security code
for you to find?
That's exactly what you did.
You knew no one would believe
you could be that careless.
You wanted us to believe
that someone else
was trying to frame you.
Ever consider
that maybe someone was?
We traced the computer station
used to enter the data.
Oh, you took us all around
the system and back again
before we could locate
the source,
but it was this station
in sick bay.
I'd almost say
it was a Maquis operation,
if I didn't already know
you were a Cardassian.
Computer, activate emergency
holographic medical program.
Ah.
Have I been called
to testify?
Before you even mentioned
Orkett's disease to me,
the doctor had
already discounted that
as a possible explanation
for your blood anomalies.
DOCTOR:
And may I say a doctor less
informed about Bajoran medicine
might have been fooled,
but my program includes
the complete Bajoran medical
text on Orkett's disease.
There's no way
any childhood virus
or Cardassian
bone marrow transplant
can explain away the genetic
markers in your blood.
You are Cardassian, Ensign.
But that didn't necessarily
make you the traitor
we were looking for.
We needed more evidence,
and you gave it to us.
The one thing
I still can't understand is...
why?
I did it for you.
I did it for this crew.
We are alone here,
at the mercy
of any number of hostile aliens
because of
the incomprehensible decision
of a Federation Captain.
A Federation Captain
who destroyed
our only chance to get home.
Federation rules,
Federation nobility,
Federation compassion?
Do you understand?
If this had been
a Cardassian ship,
we would be home now.
We must begin to forge
alliances.
To survive,
we must have powerful friends.
The Kazon-Nistrim were willing
to be our protectors
in return
for some minor technology.
Minor technology
that could change
the balance of power
in this Quadrant.
Change it in our favor.
That is all that matters
at this point,
building a base of power
in this Quadrant.
You are a fool, Captain.
And you're a fool
to follow her.
I can't imagine
how I ever loved you.
Computer, Command XJL.
Computer, override
transport in progress.
Unable to comply.
Security lockout is in place.
Computer, identify destination
of transport.
A Kazon vessel,
14 kilometers off the port bow.
Bridge to Janeway.
Go ahead.
The Kazon ship
is powering up its engines.
It looks like they're
getting ready to go to warp.
Ready a tractor beam.
I've also got two Kazon warships
on an intercept course
less than ten minutes away.
TUVOK:
Captain, even with our superior
defense capabilities,
we cannot prevail against
three Kazon warships.
Awaiting your instructions,
Captain.
Power down the tractor beam.
Set a course out of here,
Mr. Paris, warp four.
Engage when ready.
Yes, ma'am.
We'll have to wait for another
day to settle up with Seska.
Can I ask you to be honest
with me, Lieutenant?
As a Vulcan, I am at all
times honest, Commander.
That's not exactly true.
You lied to me
when you passed yourself off
as a Maquis to get on my crew.
I was honest
to my own convictions
within the defined parameters
of my mission.
You damned Vulcans
and your defined parameters.
That's easy for you.
On the contrary. The demands
on a Vulcan's character
are extraordinarily difficult.
Do not mistake composure
for ease.
How may I be honest
with you today?
I'd just like to know,
from someone else who pulled
the wool over my eyes,
was I particularly naive?
Was I not
paying enough attention?
What the hell was it that
let all you spies get by me?
Like all humans,
you depend on feelings
and instincts to guide you,
and they invariably
let you down.
But "particularly naive"?
No, Commander,
and I've always considered
your attention span
to be adequate.
Did you ever see anything
about Seska
that made you suspicious?
No. She quite expertly
"pulled the wool"
over my eyes as well.
Well...
that makes me feel
a little better. Thanks.
Curious.
What?
That my failure,
added to your own,
should improve your feelings.
Misery loves company, Tuvok.