CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 48693.2.
We've altered course
to investigate
some unusually intense
photonic activity
in a nearby protostar.
Lieutenant Torres and I
are beaming aboard samples
for further analysis.
Containment field is active.
We're ready for transport.
Energize.
That's strange.
Both containers
should have been filled.
Here's the problem.
A slight breach
in the annular confinement beam.
I'm aborting transport.
Okay, let's try
that again.
Energizing.
All right.
I'll get a complete
phase spectrum analysis
on this as soon as possible.
If this photonic matter
works as well as I think,
it could boost
the efficiency
of our power converters
15 percent.
I'd say more like 20.
How long will it
take to finish
the preliminary
analysis?
Um, six hours, maybe more.
I'd like to get it
sooner than that.
I believe Ensign Kim
is off duty.
Could you use his help?
Can you convince him
to give up his free time?
I think I might
be able to.
Janeway to Kim.
That's odd.
Computer, locate Ensign Kim.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Ensign Kim
is not aboard the ship.
Sensor logs show no record
of any unauthorized
transporter activity,
and all shuttlecraft
are accounted for.
If Ensign Kim left the ship,
he did not do so by
conventional means.
His last shift ended
four hours ago,
and he was scheduled for time
on Holodeck 2
when he went off duty.
No one has seen him since.
Scan the holodeck.
What's the matter?
There is significant
interference in the holodeck.
I cannot obtain
a clear scan.
Is it a system
malfunction?
I do not believe so.
Commander.
TUVOK: The holodeck
is definitely active.
There appears to be
a program in progress.
Can you shut it down?
The manual overrides
are not functioning.
I cannot terminate the program.
All right,
let's go in.
( tricorders beeping )
( theme music playing )
Computer, identify program.
COMPUTER:
The program in progress
is a holonovel based
on the epic Earth poem
Beowulf.
Beowulf?
An ancient English epic
set in sixth century Denmark,
if I remember correctly.
It's about a hero
named Beowulf
who fights a creature
that's terrorizing a kingdom
and murdering its subjects.
Monsters and swordplay,
that sort of thing.
I'm not detecting
any life signs,
but there is still
considerable interference.
I can't determine
the source.
Speak as a friend
or stand challenged.
Computer, delete character.
The holodeck
command systems
must not be
functioning either.
We must also consider
the possibility
that the safety programs
are malfunctioning as well.
I'm am Freya,
shield-maiden,
daughter of King Hrothgar.
I hold this guard post
against any intruders
who would bear us harm.
So declare yourselves.
I will hear
your answer
before you march any further
through this land.
We have no desire
to trespass.
However, we are on
an urgent mission,
so if you would allow us
to continue,
we would
appreciate it.
What land do you call home?
Your faces tell me
you are not men of the Danes.
Are you...
kinsmen of Beowulf?
Yes. We are
Beowulf's kinsmen.
My name is Chakotay,
and this is Tuvok.
Have you seen Beowulf?
Yes.
He was like no other.
Hair straight and raven black,
eyes bright with fierce fire,
the burning gaze of a hero.
Grandiloquence
notwithstanding,
that would qualify
as a description of Mr. Kim.
How did you know
he was Beowulf?
This is Harry's
holonovel.
It'd make sense that
he'd be playing the hero.
She might be able
to help us figure out
what happened to him.
A reasonable assumption.
Your kinsman was
a truly noble warrior.
It is right you should
avenge his death.
Yes, but first,
we'd like to know more
about how Beowulf died.
Of course.
Come.
I will take you to the king.
Hail, Lord Hrothgar.
I bring new friends,
Chakotay and Tuvok,
kinsmen of Beowulf,
who come to avenge his death.
Greet them well.
I would bid you welcome
to my hall,
but the days of glad tidings
are gone from this place.
We grieve with you
for your kinsman.
We had hoped that a warrior
of Beowulf's strength and renown
would be able to deliver us
from our curse.
Could you tell us exactly
what happened to him?
He met with
the same fate
as did 30 of
our own warriors.
Grendel.
That's the monster
who's been attacking you.
Repelled by light and laughter,
the beast waits
until we slumber.
Then, bereft of remorse,
Grendel comes in murderous rage
to my hall
to take my people,
and there is nothing
anyone can do
to stop it.
If you are wise,
you will forego your vengeance
and return home.
Death lives here now.
My Lord is fatigued.
It is time to retire.
TUVOK:
We would like
more information
about Beowulf.
Would it be possible
to examine his body?
The body of
Beowulf is gone.
Dragged down to
Grendel's foul lair,
no doubt.
The beast leaves no traces.
Did anyone actually
see the battle?
No. Beowulf chose
to face Grendel alone.
Then I think we'd like to see
this Grendel for ourselves.
To what purpose?
To raise false hopes
in our king again
as did your kinsman?
Leave us alone
in our misery.
FREYA:
Unferth!
These men are our guests.
You will show them
the hospitality they deserve.
They deserve nothing!
If their Beowulf was truly
the champion he claimed to be,
then Grendel would be dead,
his head mounted on a spear.
Instead, we spend yet
another night in terror.
TUVOK:
If you would allow us
to assist you, perhaps we could
help alleviate your terror.
Your names mean nothing to me.
There are no songs of your deeds
nor stories of the battles
you have fought.
Who are you to believe
you can slay Grendel?
We have no intention
of slaying anyone.
We simply wish to examine
the creature.
( laughs )
Grendel might not wish
to be examined...
without a fight.
And if you would fight Grendel,
then you will first
prove your worth to me.
Defend yourselves.
You are able warriors.
You may stand sentry tonight.
You are brave men.
I hope to see you again,
fate permitting.
Chakotay to Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, we haven't found
any definite signs of Harry,
but we've encountered
several holodeck characters
who claim to know
what happened to him.
TUVOK:
Mr. Kim was running a holonovel
based on the poem Beowulf.
According
to the holo-characters,
he attempted to battle
a creature of some kind
and was killed in the process.
Killed?
Since the safety programs
are malfunctioning,
we must consider
the possibility.
But...
you haven't found a body?
No. If we shut down the program,
we'd know if he's here or not.
Run a diagnostic
on the holodeck's
imaging control systems.
If they're not working,
try to repair them.
And relay your tricorder
scans to the Bridge.
I'd like to analyze
your readings.
CHAKOTAY: Aye, Captain.
Chakotay out.
The primary imaging matrix
should be here
behind this wooden panel.
I will attempt to locate
the auxiliary matrix.
This ancient Earth culture
seems fascinated with monsters.
Every culture
has its demons.
They embody the darkest emotions
of its people.
Giving them physical form
in heroic literature
is a way of exploring
those feelings.
The Vok'sha of Rakella Prime
believe that hate is a beast
which lives inside the stomach.
Their greatest
mythical hero
is a man who ate
stones for 23 days
to kill the beast,
and became a saint.
Such fables are necessary
only in cultures
which unduly emphasize
emotional behavior.
I would point out
there are no demons
in Vulcan literature.
That might account
for its popularity.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Chakotay.
Chakotay here.
Commander, we've analyzed
your tricorder data.
A deep-level scan shows minute
quantities of photonic energy.
How could it be
in the holodeck?
We think it happened
when we beamed aboard
the samples
from the protostar.
There was a breach in
the annular confinement beam,
and photonic energy
must have leaked
into the transporter system.
And from there into
other ship systems as well.
We've already found some
in the replicators.
TUVOK:
That raises an uncomfortable
possibility, Captain.
If the holodeck's conversion
nodes were contaminated,
Ensign Kim may have
inadvertently undergone
the process
of matter conversion.
You're saying he might have
been converted into energy?
We have to consider it
a possibility.
After all, the holodecks
are basically an outgrowth
of transporter technology.
Changing energy into matter
and back again.
Every time a program is run.
Except it's not supposed
to convert people.
CHAKOTAY:
Hold on, Captain.
Something's coming.
( unearthly howling )
It is an object approximately
one meter in diameter.
I think Grendel may
be paying us a visit.
Captain, the
holo-characters told us
Kim was killed by Grendel.
An examination of this part of
the program might be advisable.
Proceed.
Captain, I'm picking up signs
of matter/energy conversion.
Emergency transport.
Get them out
of there now.
I can't get a lock.
( unearthly howling
intensifies )
Commander Chakotay, report.
Mr. Tuvok?
Captain, I've lost
their life signs.
They're gone.
TORRES:
This is a scan of the holodeck
just before we lost contact
with Chakotay and Tuvok.
The readings are pretty garbled,
but I'm still inclined to think
that there is a malfunction
in the holodeck's
matter conversion nodes.
Photonic energy leaking
into the subsystems
could certainly
damage the nodes,
and it might have created
a defect in the program
that occurs
when Grendel shows up.
A defect that dematerialized
our people.
I'm not willing
to accept the fact
that Harry and the others
are gone for good.
Their molecular patterns
might still be there.
And if they are, we might be
able to rematerialize them.
The only thing we can do is
go back into the holodeck.
Study this... energy surge.
Find out what
exactly happened.
Anyone who goes
back in there
might wind up
just like the others.
Maybe not anyone.
Me?
PARIS:
A hologram can't be
converted into energy.
It already is energy.
You're
the perfect choice.
How do you intend to transfer me
out of Sick Bay?
We'll have
to modify
your data stream
protocols
and imaging
systems,
but the fact that
you're going
to the holodeck
simplifies things.
The projection
systems
are already
in place there.
And we're going
to give you
complete control
over your magnetic
containment field.
You'll be able to
make yourself solid,
or let matter pass
through you at will.
Nothing on
the holodeck
will be able
to touch you--
unless you
want it to.
I see.
Think of this as your first
away mission, Doctor.
I can understand
your hesitation,
but there are three
lives at stake,
and you have
the best chance
of anyone on this ship
to save them.
Do you
understand that?
Yes.
Good.
Your job is to find
the photonic energy surge
and scan it closely.
We need all
the data we can get.
You'll have to interact
with the characters
in the holonovel,
so make sure you're familiar
with the Beowulf story.
Your circuit
modifications
will be finished
in three hours.
Yes, Captain.
( door opens, closes )
Computer,
access full text
of ancient Earth epic Beowulf
including historical annotation
and cultural references.
Data compilation in progress.
Doctor?
Ah, Kes.
Come in.
I don't know
how long I'll be gone,
but my absence is no reason
to suspend your studies.
How are you doing
with the protein synthesis text?
I finished it
yesterday.
Good. Then you may
as well start learning
how to operate
the base-pair sequencer.
You'll find the manual
in the technical data base.
Was there
something else?
There's something
bothering you.
Not at all.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have a great deal
of preparation to do.
You're nervous about
this mission, aren't you?
Nervous?
I can perform emergency surgery
without getting nervous.
I can make life-or-death
decisions about patients
without getting nervous.
What makes you think
I'm nervous?
Those things are
familiar to you.
You've been programmed
to do them, but...
this is different,
isn't it?
I can describe every detail
of every piece of equipment
in this Sick Bay-- from bio-bed
to neurostimulator--
but I've never even
seen a sky or a forest,
let alone Vikings and monsters.
I can't afford to fail.
But I don't know what to expect
in that holodeck.
You've been telling
me that you
deserve to be treated
like a member of the crew.
Well, here's your chance.
And I can tell you
that none of the crew
knows exactly what to expect
when they go on an away mission.
Doctor,
have you chosen
a name for yourself yet?
I have narrowed the list
to three possibilities.
Then let me suggest
you choose one before you go.
It might help you feel more
like a Starfleet officer.
Hm.
You may be right.
I'll give it some thought.
And Kes...
thank you.
Good luck.
Paris to Janeway.
We're ready
for the transfer, Captain.
JANEWAY:
Good. Go ahead.
How about you,
Doctor?
You ready?
Of course.
I've already transported
a tricorder
onto the holodeck.
Engaging transfer
circuits... now.
JANEWAY: Is everything
all right, Doctor?
Yes. There were no problems
with the transfer.
I'm on my way.
Speak as a friend
or stand challenged.
I am...
Yes, you're Freya,
the king's daughter.
A female warrior
known as a shield-maiden.
We have never met,
and yet you know my name?
Are you a sorcerer?
No.
It's simply that...
your reputation precedes you.
A warrior of your skill...
You're quite famous
where I come from.
I did not know
that word of my deeds
has carried to other lands.
Tell me what you have heard.
Well... your battle with...
Scyld the Gar-Dane?
...is practically legend.
An incredible story.
I burned his hall
to the ground.
There was nothing
left but ashes!
Charming.
And did you
hear of my campaign
against the heatho-bards
to the south?
I fought them for--
I'd be delighted
to hear all about it,
but I'm on an urgent
mission of my own.
I'm looking for Grendel.
( sighs )
Only a warrior would seek
that which others flee.
What is your name?
I'm glad you asked.
My name is... Schweitzer.
Dr. Schweitzer.
"Schweitzer."
A hero's name.
Come, I will take you
to the king.
Hmm.
FREYA:
The hall is not far from here.
Look, fortune
is with us.
Atuta, a most
powerful plant.
What exactly do you
intend to do with it?
We brew the atuta
into a broth,
which we drink
before battle.
It brings on
the spirit of the bear
and gives us strength
to swing our swords.
It's more likely to bring on
profuse sweating,
convulsions,
and acute delirium.
This is
an Amanita muscaria--
a fungus common to
subartic climates,
and, let me assure you,
quite poisonous.
Yes, but those
it does not kill,
it makes strong.
A most hearty plant.
Are you a master
of herb-lore?
Well, in a way,
I suppose I am.
You are truly a man
of many talents,
Lord Schweitzer.
Your people must
value you greatly.
You would think so.
Hail, Lord Hrothgar!
I bring a new friend,
Schweitzer,
who has come
to destroy Grendel.
Greet him well.
I would bid you welcome
to my hall,
but the days of glad tidings
are gone from this place.
DOCTOR:
I'm sorry
to hear that,
but with your permission,
sir, I'd like to stay
here tonight, and
wait for Grendel.
To what purpose?
To raise false hopes again,
as have others before you?
Leave us alone
in our misery.
I'm afraid
I can't do that.
I have a mission.
Your name means
nothing to me.
There are no songs
of your deeds
nor stories of the battles
you have fought.
Who are you to believe
you can slay Grendel?
I'm simply a... warrior.
I'm only concerned
with Grendel.
I have no quarrel
with you.
Indeed you do,
and if you will fight Grendel,
then you will first
prove your worth to me.
Defend yourself!
Fate be with you.
( laughter )
( yelling )
( laughs )
If this is your best,
then you should thank me.
Grendel would
destroy you
with far greater
ease than I.
( sighs )
This is absurd.
So be it.
( yells )
( screaming )
( groaning )
You might want to put
some ice on that.
It'll take down
the swelling.
Our time of deliverance
is at hand.
We have been given
a new champion--
one whom weapons
cannot hurt.
The one who will
destroy Grendel
and end
our suffering.
All hail the hero!
All hail Schweitzer!
WARRIORS:
Schweitzer! Schweitzer!
Schweitzer!
Eat, eat.
What is it?
Elk.
When I built this hall,
the forest ran
thick with them,
but today,
game's more scarce.
Enjoy it, Lord Schweitzer.
It is a great delicacy
in our land.
Hmm. It's quite good.
We rarely hear stories
of other lands.
Honor us with a tale
of your home
to gladden
our hearts.
I'm not much of a storyteller.
Please... indulge us.
Ach, tell us a tale
of your prowess in battle.
Well, there was the time
I managed to stop the spread
of Parinisti measles
before it
became epidemic.
For a while,
things were touch and go.
Six people came down with it.
Fortunately, I was able
to isolate the endoplasmic virus
and replicate it
in order to form an antibody.
Even then, it wasn't
altogether clear
I could create
an effective vaccine.
But I worked at it
for 74 hours straight
and managed to create
an inoculation
that successfully protected
the crew.
You'll excuse me,
My Lord,
if I take leave
of this... folly.
A truly unique tale.
Come, Lord
Schweitzer.
Allow me to show
you my home.
If you are in need of anything,
please do not
hesitate to ask.
All I need is
to find Grendel.
You are
a true champion--
always ready
for the fight.
Ah, perhaps you
would like some mead
to fortify yourself
for battle?
No, thank you.
I'm fine.
Away. You're disturbing
Lord Schweitzer!
It was with that weapon
I made my first kill.
I was 11 years old.
You killed someone
when you were 11?
Well, it's a poor
weapon, I agree,
but a token of my youth.
You must have
similar trophies
from your own childhood.
I... don't remember much
about my childhood.
Well, I am certain
you distinguished yourself
in battle many times
and did honor to your father.
My Lord, it
grows late.
It is time to retire.
Always with you
it is time to sleep.
Perhaps you have forgotten
that the work of a warrior
is battle, not rest!
You would do well to learn
from Lord Schweitzer.
This was
a beautiful hall once...
before Grendel.
You will make it so again.
You have our thanks.
I appreciate your faith
in me, Sire.
Come, my lord.
You may have deceived
them with your tricks,
but the king is old
and desperate for hope,
and the rest are just fools!
You have nothing
to worry about, Unferth.
Once I'm done with Grendel,
I'll be leaving.
We shall see.
The morning will prove
if your deeds are
as strong as your words.
The nights here are cold.
I wanted to make certain
you were comfortable.
I appreciate
your concern.
I thought everyone
had gone to sleep.
Sleep does not come
easily in this place.
Not anymore.
I was taught the world
would end in winter.
First, there would
be a desperate cold,
followed by a demon who
would devour the sun.
It has been long
since we felt summer,
and a demon does
walk these halls.
Freya...
your world
isn't coming to an end.
Perhaps not,
but it has changed.
Every night
the monster comes,
and every day our
numbers are lessened,
and no one will
speak of it.
No one speaks of the fear
that he will be next.
But each meal becomes
quieter than the last,
and after a time,
we barely speak at all.
Do you know what it is
to be alone among many,
and unable to speak
your fears?
I think I do.
How do you survive?
I'm still learning how.
I'm sure that's
not very helpful.
Sometimes I believe
I can see the moment
of my own death.
It comes in battle,
I think,
my sword raised high.
It is said that
fate often spares
a doomed warrior, if
his courage can prevail.
But there have been days
when I felt my
own courage falter...
and then you came.
I'm glad I could help.
Perhaps I can
help you.
Before combat,
it is most important
to stay warm.
( clears throat )
Well, you've done
an excellent job
with the fire.
I'm sure I'll--
Fire is not
the only heat,
Lord Schweitzer.
You know where I sleep.
( sighs )
( unearthly howling )
Holodeck to Bridge.
JANEWAY:
We're monitoring you.
Captain, I'm picking up
readings of photonic energy.
( unearthly howling
intensifies )
Captain, it's right
in front of me.
It's some kind of...
photonic energy formation.
Emergency!
Get me out of here!
Now!
Sick Bay, emergency transfer.
I'm on it.
JANEWAY:
Sickbay, report.
Uh... I have him, Captain...
more or less.
I think you better come
take a look at this.
How does it feel?
Just like the old
one, actually.
Apparently, contact
with photonic energy
disrupted
your magnetic cohesion,
but we're still not sure
if that's what happened
to the others.
TORRES:
Captain, take
a look at this.
The readings from the
Doctor's tricorder
when the energy surge
made contact with him.
They're showing
a synaptic pattern.
I wouldn't expect to see
something like this
in photonic energy.
Is this the first time
those patterns
have shown up like this?
Yes, but it's
the first time
we've had clear readings
from a moment of contact.
I wonder if I could produce
these same patterns
in the samples
we have in Engineering.
If you can,
you might be able
to get more information
about how photonic energy
damaged the holodeck systems.
I'm on it.
I'll give you a hand.
PARIS:
Okay...
I've initiated
a polarization field.
I'm introducing it
into the container.
We're getting
a reaction.
It's producing a synaptic
pattern all right--
highly complex.
( loud hissing )
What's that?
( warning beeps )
PARIS:
Whatever it is,
it's cutting
through the bulkheads.
Let's get a containment field
around it.
It's heading for
Deck 14, Section C-5.
Okay, now I've got
a containment field
blocking it.
Whoa.
It's changing direction.
It's like it's avoiding
the containment field.
Let's give it another try.
Now it's blocked on three sides.
It's changing
course.
Heading for
the open side.
( sighs )
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Those synaptic patterns...
could be some sort
of neural net.
We may be dealing
with a life-form.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Engineering.
Torres here.
We're detecting an energy mass
moving through the ship.
Right. It broke through
the sample container.
Captain, it's showing
the properties of a life-form.
A life-form?
It seems to have
a neural net,
and it's demonstrating
signs of intelligent behavior.
It's cutting it's way
through the ship.
Heading for the outer hull.
It'll breach
in about 15 seconds.
Are there any critical systems
in its path?
Negative.
Then let it go.
Be ready to seal the hull breach
with a force field.
I'll have a damage control team
standing by for repairs.
And let's track it on sensors
when it gets out.
Captain,
it's penetrating the outer hull.
Force field
is in place.
I'm showing the energy form
100 meters off our port side.
Let's get it on screen.
What was that?
JANEWAY:
It appears to be some kind
of photonic lattice.
And it seems pretty clear
that the energy form
was trying to get
back to it,
as though it's...
a shelter of some kind.
Or maybe
a transportation device--
their equivalent of a ship.
At any rate,
we had sensor contact
for a few seconds,
and we picked up
three distinct bioelectrical
patterns inside it.
Bioelectrical?
What are you suggesting,
Captain?
We have three missing crewmen.
Our best guess
has been that they were
somehow converted into energy
while they were on the holodeck.
We find no sign of them
on this ship.
Then we pick up three discrete
patterns in that lattice,
three patterns that don't match
anything else in the lattice
and which have
biological components.
I don't think it's a stretch
to hypothesize
that those are our crew members
converted into a kind
of photonic energy.
But what are they
doing over there?
How did they get there?
We have good evidence now
that there are photonic beings
that live in that protostar--
life-forms
that have intelligence.
We didn't know that
when we beamed those
energy samples on board.
We had no idea
that what we were doing,
in essence, was capturing
those life-forms.
We locked them
in a containment field,
and began to experiment
on them.
If my people were
taken like that...
I know
what my response would be.
I would do
whatever was necessary
to get them back.
Then you think
they have simply...
retaliated against us?
Yes.
These beings can manifest
themselves on the holodeck
in the matrix
of a holo-character.
That's how they
were able to take
our crew members hostage.
Captain, if you're
right about this,
then we should return
the remaining life-form.
A gesture--
to show we mean well.
It's certainly worth a try.
If I took the life-form
onto the holodeck
and release it to Grendel,
maybe they'll understand
and release our people.
Ordinarily, officers go
through intensive training
before they're put
into a First Contact
situation...
but you're the only one
who can do this safely.
I'd like to finish
what I started, Captain.
I can do this.
I agree.
Make arrangements
to transfer the life-form
to a container, so the Doctor
can carry it.
But, remember...
if you're holding
the container,
you'll have to stay
in solid form.
I understand.
Freya?
Freya!
Lord Schweitzer!
We thought the Grendel
had taken you.
Not... entirely.
How did you survive?
That would be difficult
to explain,
but that's not
important right now.
This is a talisman
to destroy Grendel...
UNFERTH:
You lie!
No man could survive
an encounter with Grendel
unless he were
in league with the beast.
You have brought that talisman
to destroy us all.
That is not true.
He has returned
to help us.
No!
You speak his lies now.
He has bewitched you.
Unferth, I need to get
this talisman to the hall.
Then that gives me
reason enough
to make sure it
never gets there.
( grunting )
No! Please!
You don't know
what you're doing.
( grunting )
( yells )
Prepare to die, demon.
( groaning )
Freya...
My Lord...
My time has come.
Freya, I'm sorry.
There's nothing I can do.
It is a good death.
Take my sword.
Stop Unferth and Grendel.
I won't forget you.
Then I die happily...
with your name on my lips.
Farewell...
Schweitzer.
Here, Sire.
My Lord...
you know me
as a true warrior.
You know I am
the one hope you have
to rid your kingdom of Grendel.
That talisman will aid me
in my conquest.
I must have it.
Do not listen to him.
He has already
killed Freya.
( gasping )
Stop him, my Lord!
He is a madman!
The only reason you won't die
is that I've taken an oath
to do no harm.
Grendel...
I'm ready for you.
( unearthly howling )
( exclamations of dismay )
I don't know if you
can understand me--
but watch.
I'm setting this one free.
There's no need
for any more of this.
Please...
we ask you
to return our crew.
( console beeping )
Captain, the photonic lattice
has reappeared.
Scan it. All sensors.
I'm reading a massive
particle surge
on our holodeck.
The lattice
is gone again.
DOCTOR:
Holodeck to Bridge.
Go ahead, Doctor.
What is it?
We have them back,
Captain,
all three of them.
Good work, Doctor.
Yeah. Good work.
Would you mind telling me
where I was?
CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 48710.5.
Since the return
of our missing crewmen,
we've been unable to locate
any further traces
of the photonic aliens.
I don't know
if the being
understood language
or just my behavior.
It would have
been interesting
to pursue the relationship
further.
It's one of the most
exciting aspects
of space exploration--
meeting new species,
establishing communication,
sharing differences
and similarities.
I'm sorry none of that
happened this time.
But it did.
It just didn't happen
in very predictable ways.
But if you think about it,
we entered into conflict,
communicated,
and eventually established
a peace treaty with them.
I'm placing a special
commendation in the logs
for exemplary performance
by the Chief Medical Officer
during his first away mission.
Thank you.
I'd like to cite you by name.
Kes tells me you've chosen one.
Is that true?
I had... but I'm not sure
I want to keep it.
The last time I heard
that name spoken
was a... painful one.
I don't think
I want to be reminded.
Sounds like you had
quite an adventure
on that holodeck, Doctor.
Yes, I would say so.
Well...
something tells me
you haven't had
your last one.
( door opens, closes )
Something tells me
the same thing.
( theme playing )