CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 48734.2.
Sometimes it's a good idea
to get away from being
a captain for awhile.
To that end,
I've started participating in
a new holonovel.
The setting is ancient England.
( thunder crashing )
WOMAN:
The drawing room
is in here.
Bridget, take
Mrs. Davenport's cape
and tell Lord Burleigh
that she's here.
Yes, ma'am.
There's tea.
That would be lovely.
Thank you.
Tea is usually served at 5:30,
and dinner's at 8:30.
His Lordship doesn't appreciate
being kept waiting.
I'll be sure to be prompt.
Yes, ma'am.
Let's make something clear,
Mrs. Davenport.
My job is to make sure
that this household
runs smoothly.
I have been with Lord Burleigh
for nearly 20 years
because this household
runs smoothly.
He has come to trust me,
and I will not brook
any behavior
that might jeopardize
that trust.
So you will be expected
to follow the rules
that I have set down.
Mrs. Templeton...
I have no wish to do anything
that might disrupt
this household,
but let me make something
perfectly clear.
I have been hired
by Lord Burleigh,
and it's his orders
I will follow, not yours.
You would be wise
not to make an enemy of me.
I can make sure
we have another governess
by next week.
I suggest we try to get along,
Mrs. Templeton.
Surely there's room here
for both of us?
One lump or two?
Two, please.
Lord Burleigh will
be here directly.
( sighs )
( clattering )
( gasping )
Forgive me.
I've startled you.
I'm sorry.
I didn't hear you come in.
Mrs. Davenport,
I'll come to the point.
I am not an easy man
to live with.
Since my wife died,
I'm told I'm even worse.
She was a buffer
for me.
I understand.
The children
are the ones
who've suffered.
I've not been much
of a father to them,
and God knows,
I can't be a mother.
I'm not asking
that you replace their mother,
but I think they'll respond
to a woman's sensibilities.
You might fill a void
in their lives.
I'll certainly try, Your Grace.
Young Henry
is sometimes a bit stubborn,
and little Beatrice...
misses her mother terribly.
I hope they won't make
things difficult for you.
One thing above all
I must demand.
You are never, under
any circumstances,
to go onto the fourth
floor, is that clear?
KIM:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Mr. Kim.
I've got Commander Chakotay
and Mr. Tuvok's shuttlecraft
on long-range sensors,
but they're not responding
to our hails.
The shuttle's
been badly damaged.
I'm reading
multiple hull fractures.
Life signs?
Two, but they're very faint.
Beam them to Sick Bay
as soon as they're in range.
I'm on my way.
Aye, Captain.
Doctor.
They've each taken
a blast to the head
by some kind
of energy discharge.
Cardiostimulator.
Mr. Tuvok has
a serious concussion,
but it's nothing
I can't handle.
As for Commander
Chakotay...
all of the
bio-neural energy
has been extracted
from his brain.
Extracted?
Yes, from the
looks of it,
someone drained the energy
from every single
axon and dendrite
right down to
the synapses.
I can keep his
heart beating,
and I can keep
him breathing,
but other than that,
there's nothing
I can do.
He's brain dead.
TUVOK: The attack lasted
no more than a few seconds,
but it was highly effective.
I feel Commander Chakotay and I
are fortunate to be alive.
What happened,
Lieutenant?
We had completed our trade
mission with the Ilidarians
and were on course
to the rendezvous point
when we encountered
a dark-matter nebula.
As we began
a routine analysis,
an unidentified ship emerged
and attacked our shuttle.
Any idea why?
No. They would not
respond to our hails.
We were hit
by an energy discharge
which penetrated our shields
and filled the cabin.
Commander Chakotay
lost consciousness immediately,
and I was barely able
to activate the autopilot
before I was overcome as well.
And the alien ship?
( sighs )
The last image I saw,
was a ship
flying back into the nebula,
but the details
are difficult to remember.
Can you tell me anything
about the energy discharge--
its modulation
or phase distribution?
No. There was no time
for a detailed analysis.
However, the shuttle's sensors
may have recorded information
that could be helpful.
I will download the sensor logs.
Why would someone
want to extract
his bio-neural energy?
I don't know,
but if I'm to have
any hope of reviving him,
I must know precisely
how his neurons
were depleted.
It would be a great help
if I could examine the weapon.
We're going back
to that nebula
to try to find the ship
that attacked you.
Janeway to Bridge.
Prepare to lay
in a new course.
Mr. Tuvok will provide
you with the coordinates.
PARIS:
Aye, Captain.
We'll keep you
posted, Doctor.
TUVOK:
The energy discharge
overloaded the shuttlecraft's
central computer core.
All sensor data
have been erased.
Lieutenant Torres
is in Sick Bay now.
When she reports,
tell her to go over
those damaged sensor logs
with a fine-tooth comb
to see if she can reconstruct
any of the data.
Aye, Captain.
Well, this is going
to make things
a little more difficult.
I've been using the
long-range sensors
to analyze the nebula
you discovered.
It's sending out strong
electromagnetic radiation.
We won't be able
to scan inside it.
You know, it sounds to me
like a perfect hiding place.
I agree.
I don't like the idea
of going in there blind.
Let me see if I can
reconfigure the sensors
to a multiphasic bandwidth.
Is there a problem?
I've lost
all sensor contact
with the nebula.
I don't understand.
( beeping )
Wait a minute.
We've altered course.
Mr. Paris?
Our new heading is 121 mark 6.
We've completely
come about, Captain,
but it wasn't me.
Mr. Kim, check
the navigational computer.
Who ordered
the course change?
According to my readings,
the command was issued
from the conn.
I'm telling you, it wasn't me.
And the helm controls
are working perfectly--
no sign of a malfunction.
Ensign,
transfer helm control
to your station,
and reset our original course.
Course laid in.
Mr. Paris, I
want you to run
a full diagnostic
on the conn station.
See if you can isolate
the problem.
Aye, Captain.
You might have asked
before adorning my Sick Bay
with animal remains.
It's a medicine wheel--
a talisman
used by Chakotay's tribe.
He once...
showed me how it works.
He said if anything
ever happened to him
that I should perform
a special healing ritual.
The wheel
represents
both the universe outside
and the universe
inside our minds as well.
They believe each
is a reflection of the other.
When a person is sleeping
or on a vision quest,
it's said that his soul is
walking the wheel, but if he's
in a coma,
or near death,
it means that he's gotten lost.
These stones are
signposts...
to help point the way back.
( sighing )
Not exactly standard
medical procedure I know, but...
You've placed
the coyote stone
at the crossroads
of the Fifth and Sixth Realms,
which would divert
Commander Chakotay's soul--
that is,
his consciousness--
into the Mountains
of the Antelope Women,
according to his tradition
an extremely attractive locale.
He might not
want to leave.
How do you know about
the medicine wheel?
It's my business to know about
a variety of medical treatments,
including those based on
psycho-spiritual beliefs.
Unfortunately, in this case,
the medicine wheel
won't be much help.
There's just not enough
of his mind left to work with.
Find your way home, Commander.
Hello?
Is someone here?
KES:
It's like...
sensing some
kind of presence--
as if someone
else were here.
Your telepathic
senses again.
Is this like last week,
when you went into Sick Bay,
and you knew Lieutenant Hargrove
had been there,
only he'd left
hours before?
It's not the same.
That was like...
like hearing faint music
from a faraway place.
When I was in my
quarters just now...
Mm-hm.
it was almost tangible.
I felt like there was someone
in the room with me.
Who was it?
I don't know.
A presence.
That's all I can say.
Warp engines still within
normal parameters, Captain.
We just changed course again.
Mr. Kim?
Our new heading is 121 mark 6.
Get us back on course.
The helm's not responding.
I'm locked out.
( console beeping )
This command station
has been blocked.
From where?
The lockout originated
on Deck 12,
Section B-7--
navigational
control.
See if you can
reestablish control.
I've checked every
ODN junction
in the helm control network
and I still can't find
the problem.
Seems we've developed
a new problem
while you were gone.
Helm control reestablished.
Get us back on course
for the nebula.
Janeway to Torres.
Torres here.
Who's in the
navigational control?
No one right now.
I was there this morning,
and Lieutenant Paris
was in there
just a few minutes ago.
That's not true.
Are you certain about
that, B'Elanna?
Positive. I just saw him leave
about five minutes ago.
Janeway out.
Explanation, Mr. Paris.
I passed by
the navigational control
on my way back from the
Jefferies tube, but that's all.
Am I being accused
of something here?
We are merely
following
a line of deductive
reasoning, Lieutenant.
Both deviations from our course
were apparently issued
from locations
where you were working.
I'm telling you,
I didn't do it.
Well, I'm willing to rule out
mutiny for the time being.
I believe you, Mr. Paris,
but we have to consider
the possibility
that you might be having
a problem with your memory.
I want you to go
down to Sick Bay.
Have the doctor
check you out.
All right.
Lieutenant Durst.
Neurotransmitters at normal.
Synaptic functions stable.
Hold still.
This is an extremely
sensitive scan.
What I wouldn't give to see
good old Doc Brown right now.
What?
Doc Brown.
Lollipops in the waiting room,
no holocomic books
more than six months old,
house calls.
I caught a bad cold one time
when I was nine years old.
The doctor whipped up
a pot of garlic soup
and brought it over himself.
Your report, Doctor.
I still have
a series of tests to perform,
but other than his irritating
lapses into nostalgia,
I see nothing
wrong with him.
I guess you're going to have to
round up another suspect, Tuvok.
On the contrary,
Lieutenant.
I ran a forensics sweep of
the navigational control.
I found traces of
your DNA on the console.
That's impossible.
The cellular residue
you left behind
is less than
12 hours old.
Do you still wish to
maintain your innocence?
To be honest,
I don't know what to think.
Perhaps my biomolecular scan
will reveal something.
Keep me informed,
Doctor.
TUVOK:
I believe I have found
the ion trail
of the ship
that attacked us.
It leads directly
into the dark-matter nebula.
This is the nebula...
and this is
the ion trail.
As you can see,
their flight path
is highly erratic.
JANEWAY:
These planetoids
inside the nebula,
they may be generating
a dangerous
gravitational effect--
like storm currents.
Chances are they've
mapped those currents
and they're taking the
only safe way through.
A reasonable assumption.
I recommend we follow
their exact flight path.
Agreed. Lay in
a course to the...
KIM:
Captain, we're dropping
to impulse power.
I'm reading a massive
energy drain all over the ship,
and the warp core
is shutting down.
Bridge to Engineering.
Report.
Lieutenant Torres,
please respond.
Mr. Kim, take the Bridge.
Tuvok, you're with me.
Torres, what's going on?
Captain?
You've initiated
an emergency warp core shutdown.
What?!
Too late.
The warp core is off-line.
It'll take at least two hours
to regenerate
the dilithium matrix.
Ensign, get the rest
of the systems back on line.
Apparently, you've just crashed
the main computer,
locked out the Bridge
and stopped this ship cold.
Do you want
to tell me why?
Captain, I don't know
what you're talking about.
What the hell
is going on here?
( door opens )
I've found something
and you're not going
to like it.
This is Mr. Paris' memory engram
for the last 24 hours.
As you can see,
it has a very consistent
and distinctive modulation,
except at 1350 hours.
For one minute, 47 seconds,
a different memory pattern
appeared.
1350 hours is also
the exact moment
when Mr. Paris
presumably tampered
with navigational control.
It gets worse.
In addition
to that,
there is another disruption
at 1202 hours,
the moment when
he allegedly entered
the new course
at the helm.
I also found there's
an identical disruption
in Lieutenant Torres' pattern,
at the moment
she shut down
warp power.
I should point
out that this
is a neural
electrical signature--
what I believe to be
another brain wave
that was superimposed
on their own.
Another brain wave?
PARIS:
Whose?
I don't know.
It has an unusual
energy signature,
one I've never
seen before.
Doctor...
what are you saying?
( sighs )
One possible explanation--
and the only one
I can think of at the moment--
is that an unknown
alien entity
momentarily took control
of their minds.
Intruder alert.
All security
personnel
go to Condition 4.
Captain,
it is possible
the intruder
returned with us
in the shuttlecraft.
If we're right...
and there is an alien here,
it seems intent on preventing us
from going back to the nebula.
What's more,
it seems to have the ability
to jump from person to person.
If that's true,
it could be in any one of us,
controlling our actions
without us
realizing it.
Well, except for me.
That's true.
So far it's only affected
organic beings.
If it could control
the computer
and navigational
systems directly,
it probably would've
done it already.
Which means...
the doctor is the only
person on board
we can trust at this moment.
Doctor...
until we have eliminated
this alien presence,
I can't take the risk
that it could take over
any of the senior officers.
I'd like to transfer
all command codes to you
until further notice.
W-What would that mean?
That I am in command?
No. But you will act
as a fail-safe.
If you feel at any time
that any of us are under
the influence of the alien...
you can countermand our orders
and take control of the ship.
Do you feel up to it?
Well, of course.
I make life-and-death
decisions every day.
I feel better already.
JANEWAY:
Computer,
transfer all command codes
to the holographic doctor.
Authorization:
Janeway-eight-four-one
-alpha-six-five.
COMPUTER:
Command code transfer complete.
Let's see if we can get
the warp core
back on line ahead of schedule.
TORRES:
Aye, Captain.
Captain, I heard
what's happened.
I think you're right.
There is an alien presence here.
I've been sensing
something unusual all day.
I don't know
how to describe it,
but I know there's
something here.
Do you know where?
No. Just that
it's on the ship.
Captain, Kes's
telepathic abilities
are undisciplined.
If I could initiate
a Vulcan mind-meld with her,
I may be able to help her focus
those abilities
to detect the alien
more accurately.
I'm willing to do that.
Very well.
Proceed, Mr. Tuvok.
KIM:
The captain wants to seal off
all critical areas of the ship.
Make sure the
access hatch
of Jefferies Tube
A-17 is secured.
So what exactly
are we securing against?
We're not sure yet,
but we think
it's some kind of
noncorporeal alien.
Noncorporeal?
That means it can
probably move
right through a bul...
Medical emergency, Deck 7
Section 13-Alpha.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
It appears that Mr. Tuvok
and Kes were both hit
by an unidentified
energy discharge.
Tuvok was not badly hurt,
but Kes is in a coma.
It was similar to the attack
on the shuttlecraft--
an energy discharge
came through the bulkhead,
filled the turbolift
and hit
both of us.
We didn't pick up a
discharge of any kind
on the internal sensors.
Perhaps this type
of energy
is beyond our
sensor bandwidth.
JANEWAY:
Perhaps.
But that discharge
had to come from somewhere.
The most thorough
scanning device we have on board
is a magneton scanner.
We could search the ship
centimeter by centimeter,
but that wouldn't do much good.
This alien could be
anywhere at any time.
But what if we could perform
a magneton scan
on the entire ship all at once?
What do you suggest?
A magneton flash-scan.
We could reconfigure
every sensor array
on the ship to emit
a single burst.
It might be enough
to illuminate
any anomalous energy.
Harry, what do you think?
Whoa!
What did I do?
Stay where you
are, Mr. Kim.
I don't see
anything unusual,
but that doesn't
mean anything.
JANEWAY:
Mr. Kim?
What were you doing just now?
I was just thinking.
I was remembering
an old study I saw
about magneton scanners.
I guess my mind
started to wander a bit.
I'm very disturbed
by what just happened here.
We don't have
any idea what occurs
when someone is occupied
by this alien presence.
If we start pointing
a finger every time
someone gets distracted,
it won't be long
before outright paranoia
starts sweeping the ship.
Tuvok, B'Elanna, I want you
to get started on
that magneton flash-scan.
It's worth a try.
Dismissed.
NEELIX:
And that's not all.
Ensign Parsons
ordered his pejuta cold.
So?
He always drinks it
hot, hot!
With lemon...
but not today.
Today, it's cold pejuta,
hold the lemon.
Mr. Neelix, just because
a man changes his drink order
doesn't mean
he's possessed by an alien.
Nevertheless, don't you think
you should... scan him
or dissect him or something
just to make sure?
I could examine
every crew member
you've mentioned so far,
every person on board
for that matter,
and it wouldn't
do any good.
From what we can tell,
the alien can jump
from person to person
at will.
Sounds to me like you're
defending Ensign Parsons.
I'm not defending him.
I'm just pointing out that
you're acting a little paranoid.
In fact...
one could say you're acting
a little too paranoid.
Are you suggesting that I...?
That I could
possibly...?
Doctor, I can
assure you,
not even an alien intruder
could make me do
anything to hurt Kes.
All I'm suggesting,
Mr. Neelix,
is that paranoia is only
going to aggravate
your already precarious
emotional condition.
Try to relax.
I don't think
Kes has suffered
any permanent
neurological damage.
I'll let you know the moment
I've had any success
in reviving her.
I'll be back as soon
as you wake,
dearest,
and don't worry.
You're in good hands.
Thank you, Doctor.
What are you doing?
I am reconfiguring the
sensor relays on the ship.
This will only
take a minute.
Must you do it now?
I'm in the middle
of a treatment.
I am sorry, Doctor.
Captain's orders.
How is she?
No irreparable damage.
In fact, her injuries
are quite different
from Commander Chakotay's.
Her bio-neural energy
is completely intact,
and I'm curious
about these contusions
on her neck and shoulder.
They're not consistent
with an energy discharge.
They look more like wounds
sustained during
a physical struggle.
Odd. There was no physical
struggle that I can recall.
I just don't understand it.
The only thing these injuries
come close to resembling
is an extreme trauma
to the trapezius nerve bundle.
It's as though her nerve fibers
have been ruptured.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Lieutenant Torres and I
will be ready to initiate
the magneton scan
in approximately two hours.
You should be aware
that it will be
a high-intensity burst.
It will cause dizziness
and disorientation
in all crew members,
including myself,
for several seconds.
Make a shipwide announcement
before you initiate the scan.
Aye, Captain.
There is another matter
of some concern.
It appears that Kes's injuries
were not caused
by an energy discharge.
The doctor
has found evidence
that she was
physically assaulted.
Assaulted...
But you weren't
physically assaulted.
That is correct.
Is it possible that you
inflicted her wounds?
Me?
Maybe you were inhabited
by the alien at that moment.
It is possible.
Perhaps we should
have the doctor
run a neurological scan to see
if I show a memory disruption.
Agreed.
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Computer, activate emergency
medical holographic system.
Unable to comply.
The EMH program
has been disabled.
Disabled? By whom?
Unknown.
The doctor's initialization
routine has been locked out.
It's encrypted.
I can't reactivate the program.
It appears the lockout
originated
somewhere above Deck 4.
Why would someone
deactivate the doctor?
The doctor does hold
the command codes to Voyager.
Yes, but once
he was deactivated,
the codes automatically
reverted back to me.
If we assume the alien
could not take over
the holographic doctor,
then logically, it would try
to force the command codes
back into a humanoid host.
Me.
It's too dangerous
for one person
to retain the command codes
at this point.
I suggest we divide
my command protocols
into two
code groupings.
A sensible precaution.
You would be
the reasonable choice
to hold the second grouping,
if there's any such thing as
a reasonable choice right now.
The alien could occupy
either one of us at any time.
But, presumably, not both
of us at the same time.
I'll tell
the Bridge crew the plan.
We'll all have to act as checks
and balances for each other.
I want you all to be aware
of something that has happened--
something I must assume
was due to the alien.
The doctor has
been deactivated,
and we can't get
him back on line.
I have decided to divide
my command protocols.
Captain...
Stun her.
She's the alien.
( sighs )
That should
do it, Captain.
Thank you, Mr. Paris.
I feel better already.
Any luck getting
the doctor back on line?
Not yet.
Whoever did this
put up one hell
of a roadblock.
I'm going to have
to break through
at least six levels
of encryption
to access
the holo-emitters.
How long is it
going to take?
Two, maybe three hours.
Torres to Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, can you come down
to Engineering?
There's something here
I think you should see.
I'm on my way.
Mr. Paris?
You're our temporary medic
until the doctor returns.
Right.
Ensign, I need you
on the Bridge.
TORRES:
I've been trying
to reconstruct
the damaged sensor logs
from Tuvok and
Chakotay's shuttlecraft.
I didn't have any luck
until I ran a parity trace scan.
Captain, the sensor logs
weren't destroyed
by an energy discharge.
Someone erased them,
and then overloaded
the sensor matrix
to make it look like
they'd been damaged.
It gets worse.
There was enough
information left
in the backup logs
for me to reconstruct
what happened during the attack.
They were near
a dark-matter nebula,
and an energy discharge
did breach the hull,
but there was no other ship.
No ship?
I'm certain of it.
From what I can tell,
the energy discharge
came from the nebula itself.
Why would Tuvok lie
about an attack?
He must have been under
the alien's influence.
KIM:
Bridge to Janeway.
We're approaching
the dark-matter nebula.
Acknowledged.
How long until the magneton
flash-scan is ready to go?
The sensor arrays
are charging now.
15, maybe 20 minutes.
When it's ready,
transfer control of the scan
to the Bridge.
In the meantime,
I think we should
take a look
at exactly what it is
we're not supposed
to see.
Mr. Tuvok, can you locate
the ion trail
of the alien ship
that attacked you?
I believe so.
Mr. Kim,
lay in that course.
Shields are at maximum, Captain.
All preparations for entering
the nebula are complete.
Captain, I finished
the bio-analysis
the doctor was
running on Kes
before he was deactivated.
I think he was
onto something.
If I'm interpreting
his data correctly,
the bruises on Kes's
neck and shoulders
were the result
of a Vulcan neck pinch.
Lieutenant?
I have no memory
of injuring Kes.
Perhaps I was occupied
by the alien at that time.
Perhaps so.
But then... why does it
keep attacking you?
In three separate instances now,
it's assaulted you.
I am the Chief of Security.
It may see me
as a particular threat.
So far, you've posed no greater
threat than anyone else.
And yet, it keeps
going after you.
Captain, I believe
you are having
a typically human response
to circumstances
which are frightening
and inexplicable
commonly known as paranoia.
Maybe...
but I don't think it's paranoia
that's keeping me
from picking up
this ion trail of yours.
What bandwidth are you on?
I am using
a multiphasic scan.
If you examine the Alpha-K band,
you will see it.
Yes, here it is.
A very interesting ion trail.
There's no sign of any subspace
distortions in its wake.
According to these readings...
it's a ship without engines.
You're lying, Tuvok.
There is no alien ship
and there never was.
We're not going inside
that nebula
until we get some answers.
Mr. Kim, reverse course.
Belay that order.
That is exactly what the alien
has been trying to do--
keep us from entering
the nebula.
I suspect the captain
has been occupied.
I am relieving her
of command.
Ensign, proceed into the nebula,
one-half impulse.
Don't do it, Harry.
Now, Ensign.
No, sir.
I won't do it.
I must inform you.
This phaser is on
wide-beam dispersal
and set to kill.
I am taking command
of this Bridge.
I must ask you all
to stand together
where I can see you.
Step away
from the console, Ensign.
Captain, we're entering
the nebula.
Captain, I'm picking up
some kind of energy pulses
in the nebula--
highly coherent
with a bio-matrix.
Life-forms...
And they're
heading this way.
Those beings out there--
are they your people?
We are the Komar.
This is our domain.
What's happening?
The warp core
has been ejected.
No.
No. We must continue.
TORRES: Torres to Bridge.
Captain,
I think I was just
taken over by the alien.
One second, I was working
the plasma relays,
and the next thing I knew,
I was ejecting
the warp core.
Acknowledged, Lieutenant.
Stand by.
I don't get it.
If the alien's in Tuvok,
how could it be
down in Engineering
at the same time?
I don't know.
Unless there are
two aliens.
Two?
Wait a minute.
Lieutenant Torres
isn't authorized
to eject the warp core
on her own.
That requires a command
code authorization.
Computer, who authorized the
ejection of the warp core?
The authorization was entered
by Commander Chakotay.
Chakotay...
How is that possible?
The alien in Tuvok
wants us in that nebula,
but there's another presence
that's been trying
to keep us out.
It doesn't make sense
unless it's Chakotay.
And he knows we'll be in
danger if we go in there.
But he's in Sick Bay.
He's brain dead.
Maybe not.
Maybe his neural energy
was displaced somehow,
and he's able to move
from person to person.
Tuvok's engaged
emergency thrusters.
We're moving
again, Captain.
You brought us
here-- for what?
To extract
our neural energy?
Very perceptive, Captain.
The collective neural energy
of your crew
will sustain my people
for years to come.
You don't have to do this.
Maybe we can help you
find another source of energy.
Captain, we're
under attack.
We're being bombarded
by the energy beings.
( groaning )
( tricorder beeping )
The magneton scan identified
the entity
before it left the ship.
It was a trianic-based
energy being.
Looks like he's joined
his friends outside.
Shields are holding,
but they won't last long
at this rate,
and
the electromagnetic radiation
is blinding our sensors.
I can't find a way out.
Come about.
Maybe if we reverse course,
we can just backtrack.
Yes, ma'am.
I don't know if
that'll work, Captain.
Tuvok was navigating
a complicated course.
We could be going deeper
into the nebula.
Mr. Kim, maybe you can
reconstruct Tuvok's
navigational logs.
I'm on it, Captain.
( alarm beeping )
Shields down to 65 percent,
Captain.
The energy beings are starting
to penetrate our defenses.
KIM:
I'm not having any luck.
Tuvok deleted the navigational
logs as he went along.
He wanted to make sure
we didn't get out of here.
Neelix to Bridge.
Go ahead.
Captain, I can't be sure,
but I think I was just
taken over by the alien.
And I've done something
very strange.
I've rearranged the stones
on the medicine wheel.
If it's Chakotay,
maybe he's trying
to tell us something.
Mr. Kim, activate
Sick Bay Visual Relay 16
and put it on the viewscreen.
KIM:
Aye, Captain.
What is it?
What does it mean?
Is it a code?
A message?
Or a map...
Computer, overlay a star map
of the nebula
on the current viewscreen image.
PARIS:
The stones
are in the same position
as those three planetoids.
Chakotay must be using them
to point a way out.
Mr. Kim, lay in a course
that takes us along a line
connecting
those three planetoids.
Engage.
Shields failing!
The aliens
are penetrating the hull.
Mr. Kim, report.
We're passing the
third planetoid now, Captain.
The dark matter density
is thinning.
Reading normal space ahead.
Bridge to Torres.
Transfer all remaining power
to the thrusters--
including life support.
We've cleared
the nebula, Captain.
Main power coming back on line.
Shields at full strength.
Hull integrity normal.
The alien beings
are not pursuing.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 48735.9.
We have returned
to the coordinates
where we ejected
the warp core
and have successfully
retrieved it.
Now we're hoping the doctor
will be able to successfully
reintegrate Commander
Chakotay's consciousness.
Did it work?
It appears so.
Commander...
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm a little dizzy,
but I think
I'm all here...
How did you manage
to reintegrate
his consciousness?
It involved
three neural transceivers,
two cortical stimulators,
and 50 gigaquads
of computer memory.
I would be happy
to take you
through the process,
but it would take
at least ten hours
to explain it all to you.
Needless to say, it was
a remarkable procedure.
I would consider
writing a paper about it
if there were a convenient forum
in which to publish it.
What happened,
Commander?
After the attack on the shuttle,
I had the sensation of...
floating above my own body.
I thought I was dead.
And when the shuttle
returned to Voyager,
you were still
disembodied?
Yes.
I couldn't speak.
I couldn't touch anything.
But then I found that
if I concentrated on someone
who was in the room with me...
I could share
their consciousness.
At first, I could only
do little things
with the host's body--
push buttons, work a console.
As time went on...
it became easier to do more.
Sorry I had to
knock you around, Tuvok.
No apologies necessary.
Good job, Commander,
and welcome back.
To be honest,
I feel like I never left.
( theme playing )