MALE:
Regeneration phase completed.
Deactivate the genotron.
( genotron powers down )
Shut down
the bio-matrix.
( bio-matrix powers down )
B'Elanna...
B'Elanna Torres.
Wake up.
( theme music playing )
CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 48784.2.
We have completed our survey
of the Avery system
and are returning to retrieve
Lieutenants Paris,
Torres and Durst.
By now, they should have
concluded their inspection
of the magnesite formations
on the third planet.
Here we are, Mr. Tuvok.
One bowl of authentic
Vulcan plomeek soup.
As I have told you,
Mr. Neelix,
this is
an unnecessary indulgence.
I am quite content to eat
whatever the rest of the crew
is eating.
Nonsense!
Everyone aboard
this ship
deserves a little
taste of home
every now and then.
Very well, then.
Thank you.
Oh, don't thank me.
I'm having a
marvelous time
experimenting with
the native dishes
of the entire crew.
So far, I've
learned to make
corn salad for
Mr. Chakotay
and peanut butter
and jelly sandwiches
for Mr. Paris.
He calls it
"comfort food."
Isn't that charming?
What are you waiting for?
It's no good cold.
Well?
( coughs )
It is rather... piquant.
It is zesty, isn't it?
I tried following the recipe
in the computer's data bank,
but it seemed so bland.
So I took the liberty
of spicing it up a bit.
Call it plomeek
soup à la Neelix.
I must point out
that if you take the liberty
of changing
a time-honored recipe,
you are hardly presenting
a taste of home.
CHAKOTAY ( over P.A. ):
Senior officers, please
report to the Bridge.
But your soup.
Please...
enjoy it.
Oh!
Ooh, there's no place like home.
( burps )
The away team
hasn't arrived
at the prearranged
coordinates, Captain,
and they've failed to
respond to our hails.
Have you tried locking on
to their com signals?
We scanned the entire surface.
No sign of them.
They must still be underground.
But I can't locate them
there, either.
Then, as we suspected,
the dense magnesite formations
in the planet's crust
are blocking
our sensors.
Take a look at this.
This is the cave system
nearest the beam-in coordinates
as it appeared in our
initial geological scan
and this is
the same system now.
This tunnel here
has shifted to the west
by almost 75 degrees.
Are you saying walls
of solid rock have changed shape
in the two days since
the away team was deployed?
Apparently so, Captain,
but our initial scans
didn't indicate
tectonic activity
of anywhere near
that magnitude.
In any case, it's possible
that Torres and the others
haven't returned to the beam-out
site because they were trapped
by these
geological shifts.
I'd like to lead a team
down to investigate, Captain.
And what is to prevent us from
losing you as well, Commander?
KIM:
Bread crumbs.
Ensign?
Oh, I'm sorry, Captain.
What I mean to say is
I think I can modify
some subspace transponders
which could be deployed
along the Commander's path,
kind of like...
Bread crumbs.
Got it.
If they're placed
at regular intervals,
I believe they'll maintain
a signal link with the ship
and they could serve
as a transporter relay
in case we need to stage
an emergency beam-out.
Very well, Commander.
Take a team with you,
but I want a transporter lock
on you at all times.
Aye, Captain.
Tuvok, Kim, you're with me.
( gasping quietly )
I apologize
for the restraints,
but your presence here
is very important to us.
Do you understand?
Who... are... you?
I am Sulan, Chief Surgeon
of the Vidiian Sodality.
I demand... to know...
what is happening here.
You've surgically altered
my face!
I look like a Klingon!
I've performed no surgery,
as you understand the term.
There are several questions
I need to ask you
before we proceed.
You can't possibly believe
I'm going to cooperate
with you.
Perhaps I was in error
to leave your consciousness
and memory intact.
Durst...
Paris...
What have you done with them?!
What is your exact age,
Klingon?
If you want me
to answer your question,
you will have to answer
one of mine first.
Very well.
What... exactly...
have you done to me?
I have reconstituted
your genome.
You are now
purely Klingon.
That's not possible!
I assure you it is.
I have developed
a procedure
to stimulate
cell division.
A kind of...
enhanced mitosis.
Your Klingon
genetic material
was extracted.
It was then converted
from matter to energy
by our genotron.
Finally...
you were
rematerialized
as the purified
Klingon specimen
that you are now.
Why? Why...
have you done this?!
For generations,
my people have been searching
the Quadrant for
a species immune
to our disease, in the hope
that it would lead us to a cure.
And you think Klingons
are immune to this phage?
I believe your genetic structure
has phage-resistant
nucleotide sequences, yes.
But I needed a pure specimen
to be certain.
My people do not know it yet,
but you are their greatest hope.
I... will... never
help you!
You are very strong.
I can only hope that you will be
truly resistant to the phage.
And how will you know that?
I have infected you.
( snarls )
They're the ones
with the guns, remember?
We've got to find a way
out of this place.
Agreed, but I don't want
to do anything
until we find out what
they've done with B'Elanna.
( footsteps approaching )
In the meantime, we have to keep
track of the guards' movements--
how long are their shifts
when do they eat,
when do they sleep.
There don't seem
to be many of them.
I guess they figure
we're all so exhausted,
we don't have any fight left.
We'll find an opening, Pete,
and when the time is right,
we'll make our move.
( laughing )
Something funny, friend?
You.
Really?
How's that?
Nobody ever escapes
from this place.
Those Vidiian leeches
can yank the beating heart
out of you-- in a heartbeat.
Heart out of you
in a heartbeat.
Now, that's funny.
Hilarious.
Seems like you know this place
pretty well.
I should.
I've been here six years.
Then tell me something...
I thought those Vidiians
were in the business
of harvesting organs.
How come we're all
still in one piece?
The disease makes them weak.
They need somebody
to dig their tunnels.
That's us.
Best way to keep alive
around here
is to stay strong.
Thanks for the advice.
But don't worry.
They're always in need of
replacement body parts.
They'll get around
to gutting you eventually.
There were 23 of us
from my ship.
I'm the only one left.
Listen, when they grabbed us,
there was a woman with us--
B'Elanna Torres.
Any idea what might've
happened to her?
If she's not here,
she's been taken
to organ processing.
( beeping quietly )
I've deployed
the transponders, Commander.
The relay signal
is coming through clearly.
CHAKOTAY:
Good work.
Any sign of them?
According to my
tricorder readings,
they definitely
came this way.
The question is: Where
did they go from here?
( animal screeches )
Delightful spot
to get lost.
TUVOK:
Commander, Ensign,
over here.
CHAKOTAY:
What is it?
I detect traces of at least
five humanoid life-forms.
KIM:
Five?
There were only three
on the away team.
Evidently, they did not enter
this cavern alone.
( forceful, ragged breathing )
( door opens and closes )
Are you in pain?
It's... nothing.
Remarkable.
One of the symptoms
of the early stages
of the phage
is excruciating
joint pain.
I find it extraordinary
that you can endure it.
Some who are infected
have been known to die
from the agony itself.
It's going to take more
than an infection to kill me.
It appears you are correct.
Your body is successfully
fighting off the phage.
I am overjoyed.
How delightful for you.
Soon we will begin
a series of procedures
replicating your genetic code
and attempting various methods
of integrating your DNA
with our own.
In time, we'll be successful
and eliminate the phage forever.
When that time comes,
you will be honored
as a hero by my people.
I know I'm the first Klingon
you've ever seen,
so I'll tell you
that Klingons find honor
as warriors on the battlefield,
not as guinea pigs
in a laboratory.
Earlier, you accused me
of mutilating you.
Now you sound positively proud
to be Klingon.
You have me to thank
for that, B'Elanna.
You'll get no gratitude from me.
Perhaps you'll feel
different in time.
But I don't blame you
for your obstinance.
I would be proud, too,
with a form as handsome
as yours.
I believe Klingons
are the most impressive species
I have ever seen.
( door opens )
( groans )
Tom...
Tom, wake up.
( grunts )
B'Elanna?
Yeah. It's me.
B'Elanna, what have they
done to you?
I remember them grabbing
us outside the caves
and then I...
I guess I just blacked out.
Yeah.
They stunned all of us.
The next thing I knew,
they were waking me up in
some kind of laboratory.
I was so groggy I couldn't see.
I asked them
what they had done to me
and then one of them said
that they had completely
extracted my Klingon DNA.
( sighs )
That doesn't seem possible...
but you look human.
I feel so weak
and sick to my stomach.
Well, considering
what they've done to you,
I'm not surprised.
( gasps )
( panting )
So strange.
What?
When I was a child,
I did everything I could
to hide my forehead--
hats, scarves--
you name it.
When I was a kid,
I wore a cap
to cover the haircuts
my father
used to make me get,
first day
of every summer.
I grew up in a colony
on Kessik IV.
My mother and I were
the only Klingons there,
and that was a time
when relations
between the Homeworld
and the Federation
weren't too cordial.
Nobody ever said anything,
but...
we were different...
and I didn't like that feeling.
Then...
my father left...
when I was five years old.
( clanking,
indistinct voices )
One day he was there,
and the next, he wasn't.
I cried myself to sleep
every night
for months...
but of course,
I never told anybody.
And then I finally decided
that he left because
I looked like a Klingon...
and so I tried to look human.
Looks like you finally got
what you wanted.
Strange.
What is?
According to our last
geological scan,
this cave should continue
straight ahead
for another eight kilometers.
This is solid granite,
more than 50 meters.
If these caves were
changing configuration
while we were here,
we certainly would've felt it.
True, Commander,
but I do not believe
there has been
any tectonic activity.
I believe this wall is
merely an illusion--
a disguised force field.
Away team to Voyager.
JANEWAY:
Go ahead, Commander.
We've run into some type
of force field, Captain.
One minute, we were
reading an empty tunnel,
and the next, we walked
right into
a solid wall of rock.
Captain, the energy
configuration
of the force field matrix
is virtually identical
to those used by the Vidiians.
Mr. Ayala...
scan for any alien
vessels in the sector.
Commander, we know
from past experience
that our phasers
can disrupt that force field.
I want to find out
what's in there.
Aye, Captain.
But I don't want you
taking any unnecessary risks.
We'll be standing by to
implement an emergency beam-out.
Acknowledged.
CHAKOTAY:
It's not working, Captain.
Try reconfiguring your phaser
to match the bandwidth
modulation.
Commander!
Three to beam up!
B'Elanna.
How are you feeling today?
I feel strong.
It's very frustrating
to be restrained like this.
I sympathize.
I don't like being
chained up like an animal.
I'm sorry.
I wish there was...
I've been thinking about
what you've said.
It's because of you
that I am Klingon.
And I do...
like...
this feeling.
In a strange way,
I suppose...
I am grateful.
Did you know
that Klingon females are
renowned in the Alpha Quadrant
not only
for their physical prowess,
but for their...
voracious... sexual
appetites as well?
Why not let your creation
out of her harness?
Study her in action.
( gasps quietly )
I wish it were possible,
B'Elanna...
but I'm afraid I can't risk
releasing you just yet.
( quiet panting )
Forgive me.
For what?
Please...
don't condescend.
I may have
a grotesque appearance,
but I assure you
my instincts are finely honed,
and I do have feelings.
Hard as it may be
for you to imagine, B'Elanna,
my people were once handsome
and vigorous like yours.
And with your help,
we will be again.
Perhaps, when
that time comes...
I will not disgust you
quite so much as I do now.
They're coming to take us
to the work detail.
You can't let them see
how sick you are.
Maybe if they
think I'm too weak,
they'll leave me behind.
I could try to get my hands
on that console over there.
Or maybe they'll skip
the preliminaries
and take you straight
to organ processing.
You.
Come with me.
What for?
You asked to contact
your ship.
The Prefect wishes
to discuss your request.
I'm the senior officer here.
If your superiors want to talk
with one of us, it should be me.
He's not going
anywhere without me!
Tom, don't.
They'll kill you.
Stop!
( gasps )
It's okay, Tom.
They're the ones
with the guns, remember?
( door opens and closes )
( sniffling )
What is it?
Now that the Vidiians
know we're here,
we have to be prepared
for the possibility
that they'll call in
reinforcements.
So far,
long-range sensors
haven't located
any alien vessels near here.
However, it is possible
that the same technology
that disguises
their force fields,
cloaks their ships.
CHAKOTAY:
The other thing
we have to consider
is that the prisoners
may be at greater risk now.
KIM:
Captain, take a look at this.
Using our tricorder data,
I've been able
to scan the entire planet
for the force field signature,
and it looks like
the field surrounds an area
more than 600 kilometers
in circumference.
Is there any way
to scan inside it?
Every reconfiguration
I've tried has failed.
If it's the same kind
of force field
the Vidiians used
the last time we ran into them,
why didn't our
phasers breach it?
Apparently, it has been adapted
to repulse phaser fire.
If the Vidiians can move in
and out of there, so can we.
Start setting up
simulations.
Find a way to get through
that force field.
SULAN:
B'Elanna?
I have something
I want to show you.
Durst...
I thought perhaps this new face
would make you
more comfortable with me.
You've killed him.
Yes, B'Elanna,
but his organs will save
more than a dozen lives.
( grunting, snarling )
( choking )
( door opening )
( footsteps approaching )
Deep-level scans
have revealed
a network of microfissures,
minuscule openings
which develop briefly
each time the field
matrix remodulates.
Just how small are
these microfissures?
Less than one micron.
And they close up
within a few seconds.
Would it be possible
to use our phasers
to expand one of these
openings as it's forming?
That was our first thought.
But we realized such an attempt
would have to be at close range
and would carry the risk
of alerting the Vidiians
to our presence.
So then it occurred to us--
if we could narrow
the transporter's energy beam
tightly enough,
it might be possible
to transport one of us
through the microfissures.
Of course,
timing the transport
to the precise moment
of an opening would be critical.
But if we could
get someone inside,
we might be able
to find our people
and also deactivate
the force field.
And then, presumably,
we could beam everyone
back to the ship.
Precisely.
But you should be aware
that because we are incapable
of scanning beyond
the force field,
we will have no way
of communicating
with whoever
transports inside it,
nor will we be able
to verify
that the transport
has been successfully completed.
Moreover, what's to prevent
whoever goes in
from being captured
by the Vidiians?
I have an idea
about that, Captain.
DOCTOR:
Dermal stimulator, please.
Remarkable work, Doctor.
( scoffs )
If you think this
is remarkable,
you should see me
remove a bunion.
I have done my best
to replicate Vidiian attire.
I trust it will prove
sufficiently convincing.
It's a fine piece
of work, Mr. Tuvok.
Next time
I need a tailor,
I'll know just
where to look.
GUARD:
Quickly now!
In there!
Here, B'Elanna.
Sit down.
Here. It's water.
Thanks.
Rest while you can.
The guard won't be back
right away.
Keep it.
Tom...
I've been thinking.
When they did this thing to me,
I think it changed more
than just the way I look.
What do you mean?
Back there,
when they took Durst away...
I was...
terrified.
No one could blame you for that.
You don't understand.
I've been in worse situations,
but I've never felt
like that before.
Never.
I mean...
my heart was pounding
and my hands were shaking.
I didn't even try to help you.
B'Elanna, I'm no doctor,
but I have to believe
that whatever they did to you
has seriously depleted
your strength.
There's nothing
you could've done.
No, that's not it.
I think that...
when they extracted
my Klingon DNA...
they turned me
into some kind of...
...a coward.
Sometimes fear
can be a good thing.
It keeps you from taking
unnecessary chances.
Courage doesn't mean
that you don't have fear.
It means that you've
learned to overcome it.
And I know you can find
the courage to hold on
until we can find a way
out of this place.
GUARD:
What's going on here?
She's ill.
She needed a rest.
If she's too weak, I'll take
her back to the barracks.
TORRES:
That's okay, Tom.
Maybe from there,
I can try to make contact
with the ship.
KIM:
The emitter array has been
initialized, Captain.
Good.
Are you ready,
Mr. Chakotay?
( console beeping )
TUVOK:
Captain, there's an opening
forming in
the force field.
Initiating auto sequence.
Targeting scanners
to match coordinates.
Scanners locked.
On my mark, Mr. Kim.
Energize.
Well...
now we wait.
( panting )
Make a sound and
I'll break your neck.
Understand?
I'm looking for my friend,
Tom Paris-- a human male.
Have you seen him?
He was here,
but they sent him
to another tunnel.
Which one?
Back that way.
There was another
human with him,
but they took her
back to the barracks.
A human female?
Yeah...
( door opening )
VIDIIAN:
I need your help here.
( door closes )
( console beeps and whirs )
GUARD:
What are you doing?!
Come with us.
Where are you taking me?
For a shower
and a hot meal.
No, please!
( remote beeps )
Wake up, pahtk!
Eat!
What... What is it?
Some rodent I killed.
No. Thanks.
I'm sorry I can't
replicate you a soufflé,
but you need nourishment.
I can't carry you
all the way out of here.
How are we supposed
to escape this place?
There are guards everywhere.
We fight our way out.
Maybe you haven't noticed,
but I'm not exactly
in fighting form.
That's why you need food.
Eat!
So...
you're what's left over
when all the Klingon DNA
is taken out.
Apparently.
If I hadn't come along,
were you just going to waste
away in that prison camp
until they killed you
for your body parts?
Were you too frightened to act?
I was looking
for a way to escape.
Looking!
I'll show you
the way to escape.
This and this.
That's the way you respond
to every situation, isn't it?
If it doesn't work, hit it.
If it's in your way,
knock it down.
( huffs )
No wonder
I got kicked out of the Academy.
For which you should be
eternally grateful.
Well, I'm not.
Your temper has gotten me into
trouble more times than I can...
( sighs )
Listen to me.
Listen to us.
This is ridiculous.
Do you realize that we're each
fighting with our self?
I'm not the one
who's fighting, pahtk.
If I remember correctly,
I'm the one who rescued you
from that prison
and carried you here.
Don't you think
you could at least
acknowledge that?
Can't you even admit
that you won't be able
to get out of here without me?
I don't know that I can
get out of here with you.
Brute force
isn't going to do it.
Maybe not!
Maybe we'll die in the attempt,
but that's better
than sitting here
like frightened Tikacats
doing nothing!
There you go again--
out of control.
Just leaping into action
before you think
things through.
Fine! You stay here.
I'm getting out.
No, wait a minute.
That's not what I meant.
I'm sorry.
Please...
Just before...
you rescued me...
I logged onto the
Vidiians' computer system.
I only had a few seconds,
but I think I found a way
to access the force field
that's cloaking this place.
With a few minutes more,
I could've deactivated it.
Then Voyager
could get a lock on us.
Beam us back.
Paris, too.
It may not be as exciting
as fighting our way out,
but it stands a much
better chance of working
if... I have your help.
So... you need me.
I can't get back
to that computer without you
and you'll have to cover
for me while I work.
We can't go
to the prison barracks.
There are
too many guards there.
In the lab,
where they were holding me,
there was
a security console.
That's the last place
they would
expect us to be.
They must have taken her
to organ processing.
Tell me how to get there.
Keep your hands
off me!
Whatever you say, Paris,
but I thought you might like
to get out of this place.
Chakotay?
Where are Torres and Durst?
I think
they've been taken
to what the Vidiians
call "organ processing."
GUARD:
You!
Why are you talking
to that prisoner?
I was ordered to take him
to organ processing.
Why wasn't I notified?
I was told you had been.
I've never seen you before.
My face was just grafted.
Very well.
Take him, but from now on,
I expect to be
notified in advance
of all transfers.
Yes, sir.
There.
I have to bypass
the security code,
so I can access
the force field grid.
Then I'll have a better idea
of what we're dealing with.
That should do it.
( console beeping )
There.
That's what we're up against,
and I think we're...
here.
Can you shut it down?
I'm working on it.
( alarm blaring )
What now?
If they didn't know
we were here before,
they do now.
Take it easy.
I'll be done in a minute.
You're not frightened
anymore,
are you?
Maybe I just don't have time
to think about it.
( grunting )
Are you hurt?
Keep working!
B'Elanna!
Stop.
You're not going to hurt me.
You need me.
You're right,
but if you do not surrender,
I will kill her.
Drop it!
Who are you?
That's what I want to know!
It's Chakotay.
I think I've just
about accessed
the force field.
Hurry!
Got it!
There.
Captain, the force field
has been disrupted.
Mr. Kim, can you get a lock
on Commander Chakotay?
Chakotay to Voyager.
Do you read?
Loud and clear, Commander.
I found them, Captain.
No!
Three humans and one Klingon
to beam up.
PARIS:
She's badly
wounded, Captain.
Beam her to Sick Bay!
Don't. No time.
You showed true courage.
It makes my death...
an honorable one.
Using tissue
from your counterpart,
I can replicate
the Klingon DNA.
Then, over the course
of several days,
I'll reintegrate
that genetic material
into your
cellular structure.
Wait a minute--
you're not saying
that you're going
to change me back.
That's precisely
what I'm saying.
Your cells' ability
to synthesize proteins
has been
severely compromised.
You need the Klingon
genes to survive.
So, she's saving my life again.
I'll get started
on the DNA.
How are you doing?
( sighs ):
I'm not sure.
It's been a pretty
strange experience.
I do know
that right now...
the way I am...
I'm more at peace with myself
than I've ever been before...
...and that's a good feeling.
But...?
I'm incomplete.
It doesn't feel like me.
I guess I've had someone else
living inside of me
for too long
to feel right without her.
I'd have to say that you two
made quite a team down there.
I know.
I came to admire
a lot of things about her--
her strength,
her bravery...
I guess... I just have
to accept the fact
that I'll spend the rest
of my life fighting with her.
( gentle theme playing )
( dramatic theme playing )