He hasn't left me
with a single shot.
In that case, pal,
call a safety.
Safety?
It's a defensive strategy.
Since you can't make a shot,
the idea is to leave
the cue ball
somewhere on the table where
Tuvok can't make a shot, either.
Oh, I don't know.
It sounds cowardly.
Suit yourself, pal,
but if you leave "Vulcan Slim"
over here with an open shot,
he's got a very good chance
of running the table.
All right... safety.
Ah!
Mr. Vulcan,
let's see you reason your way
out of this conundrum.
This safety business
is a lot more satisfying
than I imagined.
I've left him with
an impossible shot.
The shot may be difficult,
Mr. Neelix,
but to say it is impossible
is an exaggeration.
Go ahead, then.
Call your shot.
Logic would dictate that if
I strike the cue ball properly,
it will deflect first off
the rear bumper, then the side,
striking the 11 ball
and causing it to roll
directly into
the corner pocket.
This I have to see.
Perhaps the ships' stabilizers
are not operating
at peak efficiency.
Yeah, and maybe Tom Terrific
over here forgot to tell you
that Sandrine's table rolls
a little to the "east."
You should have
called a safety.
JANEWAY: Janeway to Mr. Neelix.
Please report to the Bridge.
You wanted
to see me, Captain?
Yes, Neelix. We've received
a subspace message
from an approaching vessel.
They're asking for you.
Me?
The alien ship is entering
visual range, Captain.
Slow to impulse. On screen.
JANEWAY:
Do you recognize it?
That's a Haakonian shuttle.
Haakonian?
My people were at war with them
for the better part
of a decade.
They...
conquered my homeworld
more than 15 years ago.
Any idea what the Haakonians
want with you now?
None at all.
The shuttle is hailing us,
Captain.
Open a channel.
Channel open.
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
What can we do
for you?
As I stated
in my message, Captain,
I understand you have
a Talaxian called Neelix
aboard your vessel.
I'm Neelix.
What do you want?
It is a matter
of utmost urgency.
However, I would prefer
to speak with you privately.
Your life may very well
depend upon it.
Who are you?
Forgive me.
I am Jetrel.
Dr. Ma'bor Jetrel.
Neelix...
He's a mass murderer!
When I was much younger,
my family and I lived
on a moon called Rinax--
a colony with
the most temperate climate
in the entire Talaxian system.
Warm days, balmy nights...
until the Metreon Cascade.
Melodic name, isn't it?
Especially for a weapon
of mass destruction.
And Jetrel was somehow
involved with this weapon?
Dr. Jetrel was the scientist
who conceived
the Metreon Cascade,
then he led
the team of scientists
who built it.
I see.
In the blink of an eye
Rinax was enveloped
by a deadly cloud
and those lovely days
were turned into one endless,
frigid night.
More than 300,000
were killed.
But you... survived.
I had the good fortune
to be on Talax at the time
with our defense forces
preparing for an invasion
that never came.
It wasn't necessary.
The day after the Cascade
was deployed,
Talax surrendered
unconditionally
to the Haakonian
order.
And your family?
I am so sorry.
Dr. Jetrel.
Lieutenant Tuvok,
my Chief of Security.
I have heard of your
transporter technology, Captain,
but to experience it
first-hand
is truly remarkable.
Mr. Neelix has declined
to meet with you.
That's not surprising.
I'm afraid I am not
a very popular figure
among the Talaxian people.
May we show you
to your quarters?
Mr. Neelix has
given me permission
to speak on his behalf.
You indicated that he may be
in some kind of danger...
Yes. It's imperative
that he undergo
a complete medical
examination.
For what purpose?
Our war records show
that he was part of the team
that returned to Rinax
after the Cascade
in order to
evacuate survivors.
He was exposed
to high concentrations
of Metreon isotopes.
In recent years, several of
the rescuers have developed
a degenerative blood disease
called Metremia.
Is it serious?
I am afraid that it's fatal.
The disease attacks its victims
on a molecular level.
It may lay dormant
for years
but once it manifests itself,
it will cause the body's
atomic structure
to undergo fission.
The cells will begin
to disintegrate.
My equipment
is specifically designed
to detect
the subatomic signature
of the disorder.
May I ask, Doctor,
why you've taken it
upon yourself
to examine Mr. Neelix?
I've evaluated as many
members of the team
as possible,
collecting data,
in hopes that one day
my research
will lead to a cure
for metremia.
Please, try to persuade
Mr. Neelix to see me.
Each Talaxian I screen
brings me one step closer
to a cure.
Neelix, why didn't you ever
tell me about the war?
Maybe this is one experience
that can't be shared.
It's too...
hard to...
describe how I feel
to someone who didn't
see what I saw.
I'm sorry.
You have nothing to be
sorry about, Neelix.
Excuse me.
Captain, back from your
doctor's appointment already?
I'm afraid I have some...
disturbing news, Neelix.
Nothing you tell me
could make this day
any more disturbing
than it's already been.
According to Jetrel,
you were exposed
to dangerous levels
of Metreon poisoning
and may be at risk of developing
a fatal blood disorder.
He wants to screen you
for the disease.
Uh, Captain...
please tell Dr. Jetrel
that I am... touched
by his tender concern
for my state of health,
but that I'd rather
be immersed
in a pit of Krallinian eels
than be examined by him.
Neelix, if there's
something wrong with you,
we should find out.
I don't want that man
within ten parsecs of me!
I understand your feelings,
but this is your life
we're talking about.
Don't either of you find it
the slightest bit strange
that a man who has made
it his life's work
to develop a weapon
to destroy as many
Talaxians as possible
should suddenly be concerned
with this Talaxian's health?
I don't know
what his motives are.
Maybe he's trying
to undo some of the damage
his weapon caused,
but he seems sincere, Neelix,
and at this point
I have no reason to doubt him.
If the disease is fatal,
what's the point of knowing
whether I have it or not?
Our doctor is
the most skilled physician
either of us has ever met.
If you have this disease,
he won't stop until
he's found some way to treat it.
And if Jetrel discovers
you don't have the disease,
at least you'll have
peace of mind.
Peace of mind
is a relative thing, Captain.
I simply want you to hear
what he has to say,
then if you still don't
want him to examine you,
no one will force you.
Oh, outnumbered
and outflanked.
All right, then.
I surrender.
The Metreon isotopes
are unique.
Their rate of decay
is highly variable.
We have found that
it's sometimes years
before metremia sets in,
and unfortunately...
Why are you doing this?
I beg your pardon?
Is it all just
scientific curiosity?
Metreons and isotopes?
Or do you feel... guilty
about what you did?
Guilty?
I do not regret it.
I did what had to be done.
Really? It was necessary
to vaporize
more than a quarter
of a million people
and to leave
thousands of others
to be eaten away
by Metreon poisoning?
Would it make any difference
if I told you
we never thought there would be
any radiation poisoning?
That anyone close enough
to be exposed
would be killed
by the initial blast?
It was unfortunate
we were wrong.
Unfortunate?
( chuckles )
Did you hear that, Captain?
It was "unfortunate."
Neelix, I think
what Dr. Jetrel is trying...
No, Captain. That's all right.
I'm used to it.
I'm simply a scientist.
Yes, I developed the weapon,
but it was the government
and the military leaders
who decided to use it, not I.
That must be a very convenient
distinction for you.
Does it help you sleep at night?
I slept no worse last night
than I have any other night
for the past 15 years.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means I must
live with my conscience
as you must live with yours.
How many did you kill
during the war?
Gentlemen, please.
This is obviously very difficult
for both of you,
but we are not here
to debate history.
We are here to talk about
Neelix's condition.
Don't worry about
it, Captain,
because Dr. Jetrel
will have to find himself
another laboratory rodent
to help his experiments.
Because I would rather die
than help you
ease your conscience.
I do not expect you
to like me, Mr. Neelix,
nor do I hope to allay
your obvious pain
with moral arguments
but I do believe
I can help you--
if not you,
others of your race.
Isn't that more important
than punishing me?
Are you... sure
you can't do this?
Your newfound confidence in me
is flattering, Mr. Neelix,
but Dr. Jetrel has instruments
designed specifically
to analyze
Talaxian physiology.
Just get it over with.
Did I ever tell you
about the notorious
two-tailed Talchoks of Rinax?
I don't think so.
Nasty little vermin.
Sharp claws, dripping fangs.
Ew! It was quite a nuisance.
So one summer when I was a boy,
I decided to do
something about them.
I spent weeks tinkering
creating a foolproof
Talchok trap.
Once I perfected it,
I set it in the garden.
And the next day,
I found one of those beasts
pinned at the neck.
But it wasn't dead.
It was squirming and squealing
in agony.
And suddenly, it didn't
look so fiendish anymore.
It looked like
a poor, innocent animal.
What a horrible story.
Well, you see, I had become
so fascinated with my invention
that I never really thought
about how that poor creature
would suffer.
Are you finished?
For now.
So am I.
And...?
I'm sorry, Mr. Neelix.
Sorry? Why are you sorry?
I'm afraid you have
incipient metremia.
( door chimes )
Come in!
How are you feeling?
Kes, my sweet.
I'll have you know
this is not the first time
I have stared into
the gaping maw of death.
Why once, during the battle
of the Pyrithian gorge,
I faced down
an entire battery
of Haakonian artillery.
There I was with only
a small crevice for cover.
Neelix, you're
protecting me again.
I can understand your not
wanting to talk about Rinax.
I wasn't there.
You're right.
But I'm here now with you.
We have to face
this together.
Well, there's one good thing
that will come from all this.
When I first met you,
I didn't know that your species
only lived eight
or nine years.
I fell in love with you
without knowing
how lonely it would be
to live without you
after you're gone.
Now that I'm going
to die first,
I don't have
to worry about it.
Before I met you,
eight or nine years
seemed like an eternity.
It never occurred to me
that anyone could live longer.
Now that we're together,
no matter how many years
we have left,
it doesn't seem
like enough.
But the important thing
is to cherish whatever time
we have together.
Whether it's a day
or a decade.
( door beeps )
Come in.
Am I interrupting?
Please, sit down.
Captain, I must tell you
your ship is simply astounding.
I have been studying
your transporter system.
Transporter systems?
I would think
you'd be more concerned
with Mr. Neelix.
Forgive me.
But that is what
I am here to talk about.
I believe with a relatively
few minor modifications,
the transporter system
could be used
to retrieve a sample
of the Metreon cloud
surrounding Rinax.
To what end?
I've always believed
that if I could isolate
the free isotope
that causes metremia
it could be used
to synthesize an antibody.
Then theoretically
the victim's own
immune system could destroy
the disease.
Yes, Captain, and
your transporter system
makes it all possible.
Is the isotope stable enough
to be transported?
I believe so.
We could construct
a containment field
to prevent any
contamination of the ship.
And I could have
our doctor assist you
with synthesizing
the antibody.
My thoughts exactly.
Janeway to Bridge.
Chakotay here, Captain.
Have Dr. Jetrel's vessel
tractored into
the Shuttlebay.
And lay in a course
for the Talaxian system.
That's a significant
detour, Captain.
I'm aware of that, Commander.
But it may mean saving
Neelix's life.
Understood.
I'll send a message
to Talax requesting permission
to transport material
from the cloud.
In the meantime,
Lieutenant Torres in Engineering
can give you a hand with
the transporter modifications.
Thank you, Captain.
Thank you, Dr. Jetrel.
It's a very
promising idea.
( grunts )
What is it?
( coughing )
Nothing. I just think, uh...
I'm a little overexcited
about the prospects
of discovering a cure,
and all that sparring
with Mr. Neelix
does take a toll.
Maybe you should let the doctor
have a look at you.
No, I'm fine,
and there's so much to be done.
I want to start right away.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's log:
Stardate 48832.1.
Kes has prevailed upon Neelix
to allow Dr. Jetrel
to continue metabolic scans
in the hope that it will
facilitate treatment
once the antibody
has been synthesized.
Will you be needing
my assistance, Doctor?
Not until
we have the isotope.
Mr. Neelix, is there
anything more I
can do for you?
Very well then.
Computer, override command one
E.M.H. Alpha and end program.
Incredible.
A hologram
that can deactivate itself.
Is there anything
besides science
that makes your heart
beat faster, Jetrel?
Not anymore.
Now would you
please sit down?
You know what
I've been thinking?
If I'd been in charge
of the Cascade
I'd have...
I don't know, uh...
chosen a military target
or simply deployed it
on an uninhabited planet.
Somehow I don't think
I'd have targeted
innocent civilians.
The military strategists
did not think a demonstration
would work.
They wanted to show
the power of the Cascade
in all its horror.
You should have tried
to stop them!
Why didn't you speak out?
People would have listened
to you.
It would not have made
any difference.
If I had not discovered
the Cascade
it would have been someone else.
Don't you see?
It was a scientific
inevitability,
one discovery flowing
naturally to the next.
Something so enormous as science
will not stop for something
as small as man, Mr. Neelix.
So you did it for science.
For my planet.
And, yes, for science--
to know whether or not
it could be done.
It's good to know
how the world works.
It is not possible
to be a scientist
unless you believe
that all the knowledge
of the universe and all
the power that it bestows
is of intrinsic value
to everyone
and one must share
that knowledge...
and allow it to be applied,
and then be willing
to live with the consequences.
Consequences?
Who are you
to talk about consequences?
You are not the only one
to lose family
during the war, Mr. Neelix.
Your family was killed?
Nothing as clean as death.
When I returned home
after the Cascade to my wife--
my lovely wife Ka'ree--
she could not bear
to look at me.
When I would reach out for her,
she would pull away
as if had some
contagious disease.
You see, like you,
she thought I had
become a monster.
Shortly after that,
she took my three children...
and I have not seen them since.
That's a sad story, Jetrel.
But let me tell you another one.
A man goes back to Rinax
after the Cascade,
back to what
had been his home
to look for survivors.
But the impact of the blast
has set off hundreds of fires
and there's nothing there,
just smoldering ruins
and the stench of seared flesh.
But in the distance,
in the middle
of all that emptiness,
from out of this...
huge cloud of billowing dust...
he can see bodies moving,
whimpering,
coming toward him.
They're monsters...
their flesh horribly charred.
The color of shale.
One of them comes toward him.
Mangled arms outstretched.
And he can't help it.
He-- he-- he turns away,
frightened.
But then the thing
speaks.
And he knows by the sound
of her voice
that she's not a monster
at all, but a child...
a little girl.
Mr. Neelix, I...
Her name was Palaxia.
We brought her back to Talax
with the other survivors.
Over the next few weeks,
I stayed at her bedside
and watched her wither away.
Those are consequences,
Dr. Jetrel.
There is no way
I can ever apologize
to you, Mr. Neelix.
That's why I have not tried.
Did you ever think that
maybe your wife was right?
That you had become a monster?
Yes.
The day we tested
the Cascade,
when I saw that
blinding light
brighter than
a thousand suns...
I knew at that moment
exactly what I had become.
I hope you have to live
with that a very long time.
I'm afraid you will not
get your wish, Mr. Neelix.
And why is that?
( sighs )
I have advanced metremia.
I will be dead
in a matter of days.
It's your turn!
There's no open shot.
Why don't you call a safety,
Neelix?
Isn't that what you always do?
I'm no coward.
That's not what I've heard.
Wait, what are you doing?
It's my turn.
You lost your chance to play.
Now you're going to lose.
Neelix, where did you go?
Why did you leave us?
I did what I thought was right.
You were afraid!
No!
I...
Neelix...
Who are you?
It's me, Palaxia.
Palaxia?!
Why weren't you here to help us?
( gasps )
You!
You did this, butcher!
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Neelix.
H-Here, Captain.
Neelix, I thought
you'd like to know.
We're approaching Rinax.
Neelix?
Thank you, Captain.
I'll be right there.
Entering
synchronous orbit, Captain.
( door opening )
Hard to believe
that on clear nights
you could look up from Talax
and see the shimmering lights
of the colony.
The night of the Cascade,
a bright flash
cut across the sky--
so blinding that people
threw themselves
to the ground...
and everything stopped
like a moment out of time.
Then we all looked up
to see where the flash
had come from,
but the sky seemed oddly empty.
It took most of us
a few seconds to realize
it was because Rinax was...
gone.
Of course, the moon
was still there.
We just couldn't see it because
of that Metreon cloud.
TORRES:
Engineering to Bridge.
We're ready
to begin transporter
presequencing, Captain.
Acknowledged.
This brings back
too many memories, Captain.
If you'll excuse me?
Of course.
I believe I asked for
a larger container.
Correct me
if I'm wrong, Doctor,
but we're talking
about a cloud sample
large enough to contain a few
subatomic particles, right?
Yes, but the isotope
accounts for just
a minuscule fraction
of the cloud's total mass.
I want to be sure
we get enough.
Don't worry.
We do this all the time.
Presequencing complete, Captain.
I'm ready to begin transport.
JANEWAY: Proceed.
Targeting scanners.
Locking on.
Energize.
Captain, we have
the sample aboard.
The containment field
is holding.
Well done.
Janeway out.
Good luck, Doctor.
Neelix?
Neelix, are you in here?
I've been looking
for you everywhere.
Why did you take
your com badge off?
I wanted to be alone.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but I was worried.
I know how you must feel.
No, you don't know.
Not everything.
You don't know where I was
the night Rinax was destroyed.
On Talax, fighting with
the defense forces.
I was on Talax,
but I wasn't fighting
with the defense forces.
I was hiding from them.
I wasn't a hero at the Battle
of the Pyrithian Gorge.
I've never even been there.
I don't understand.
I never reported for duty.
Why not?
I thought the war was unjust,
that Talax was fighting
for reasons
that weren't
worth killing for,
or at least that's
what I told myself,
but...
the real reason
I didn't report...
was because I was a coward.
Now you know.
If the Talaxian authorities
would have caught you,
what would they have done?
During wartime,
the punishment
for refusing
military service was death.
So...
you put your life
at risk for something
you believed in
and you think that
makes you a coward.
I don't understand.
It makes me a liar.
I'd lied about it
all these years to you,
to Jetrel, to everyone.
Because you're dishonest?
Because I'm ashamed.
What an awful burden you've
carried all these years.
No wonder you're
so angry with Jetrel.
Of course I am.
He killed them all--
my mother, my father,
my little brothers.
Is that really why?
What?
Ever since Jetrel
came on board,
you've despised him.
The hurt and anger
you've held in all these years
was vented right at him,
but was it really Jetrel
you were angry with?
Is he the one you blame
for what happened?
I... I don't know.
Or was he just
a convenient target
to keep you from looking
somewhere else?
You mean...
from looking at myself?
You may be right...
but I hate him,
and I don't think
I can stop hating him.
Maybe you have to stop
hating yourself first.
Are we ready to begin
synthesis?
Computer, override command one
E.M.H. Alpha and end program.
Now just wait one...
Dr. Jetrel.
You startled me.
I'm sorry,
but I need to speak with you...
Is it possible
we could talk later?
It won't be long before I am
too weak to work.
I would like to finish
before I die.
What is that?
You're engaging in some kind of
bizarre experiment, aren't you?
What is it this time?
You don't understand.
I can help them.
NEELIX:
What do you call that?
Scientific progress?
I'm going to the captain.
Any report on Dr. Jetrel's
progress, Commander?
Not yet, Captain.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Janeway to Dr. Jetrel.
Computer, activate emergency
medical hologram.
COMPUTER:
Please, state the nature...
What the hell is going on down
there, Doctor?
Dr. Jetrel deactivated me.
He's gone now.
Computer, locate Dr. Jetrel.
COMPUTER: Dr. Jetrel
is in Transporter Room One.
And Mr. Neelix is unconscious.
It appears he's been
tranquilized.
You have the Bridge, Commander.
Security, meet me
in Transporter Room One. Tuvok.
Please, step aside, Doctor.
You must let me continue.
Lives depend on it.
We've heard that
from you before.
You're beginning to lose
credibility.
Captain, I beg you.
Let me bring them back.
Bring who back?
Who, Doctor?
Who is it you're going
to bring back?
The victims of Rinax.
He's out of his mind,
Captain.
Please, look at
my calculations.
You remember what I told you
about metremia, Captain?
How it causes the body's
atomic structure
to undergo fission.
( groaning )
It mirrors the way
the Metreon Cascade
vaporized its victims--
through bio-molecular
disintegration.
Do we have
to listen to this?
I think we should
hear him out.
What I've been working on
for the past 15 years
is a way to rebuild
that atomic structure.
What I call
regenerative fusion.
Are you saying
you're actually trying
to restore people
who were vaporized
by the Metreon Cascade?
Yes.
Given the degree
of fragmentation
you're talking about,
I don't see
how that's possible.
The electrostatic properties
of the clouds are as such
that the disassembled
bio-matter
has been held in a state
of animated suspension.
I discovered years ago
that reintegration is possible.
Is that what you were doing
with that thing in Sick Bay?
Yes, exactly.
Neelix saw it.
It was an amalgamation
of randomly fused
organic material.
Bits and pieces
of previously
vaporized bio-matter.
But if the bio-matter
in the cloud is so random,
so jumbled,
how could you reconstruct
something whole?
I used medical records
to identify the genetic coding
of a specific victim--
a test case, if you will.
Once we input his DNA sequence,
then we can isolate
his atomic fragments
with your targeting scanners,
and then rematerialize him.
What if he's right?
Captain,
Dr. Jetrel is proposing
the reconstruction
and re-animation
of a remarkably complex set
of bio-systems
from billions
of subatomic particles.
I'm afraid I have to agree.
It all sounds
very implausible.
( groaning )
You sound exactly
like my country.
I asked them for more funds
to continue my research
to help the victims
of Rinax
because I wanted
the world to know
I am not a monster.
My theories can be used
to heal as well as to destroy.
But they... they refused me,
called me
a Talaxian sympathizer
and exiled me.
Does Neelix
really have metremia?
Or was that just
a pretext
for getting us
to come to Rinax?
It was just a pretext,
Captain.
You do not have metremia,
Neelix.
You are not going to die.
Why didn't you just tell us
the truth in the first place?
Your captain
is an accomplished scientist.
She doubts my theories.
My own government did, too.
I just could not risk
being not believed again.
But...
Captain, it will work.
Captain, if there's
any chance he can do it,
you've got to
let him try.
Neelix, there are just
too many variables.
Please, Captain.
Lieutenant Tuvok,
activate the emergency
containment field
around the transporter pad.
Aye, Captain.
Emergency containment field
activated.
JANEWAY: We'll have
to retarget scanners
to the widest possible
confinement beam.
It's our only hope
of achieving bond cohesion
with such broadly
scattered fragments.
Retargeting scanners
to wide beam.
Energize.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY:
Phase transition coils
to maximum.
Aye, Captain.
Is the bio-genic
field operational?
Affirmative.
It's incredible.
Atomic cohesion has dropped
to 49%, Captain.
JANEWAY:
Pattern buffers
to maximum power.
TUVOK:
They are already at 100%.
Take them to 120,
Lieutenant.
Pattern buffers
to 120% of rated maximum.
We're losing him.
Atomic cohesion to 39%...
22%... 14%...
His pattern
is degrading rapidly.
You must increase the power
to the pattern buffers, Captain!
We've got
to stimulate cohesion.
Is there any way to augment
the bio-genic field?
The degree of fragmentation
is simply too great.
It will not work. We are
overloading the system.
Shut it down, Mr. Tuvok.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY: Captain's log:
Stardate 48840.5.
Dr. Jetrel's metremia is now in
its final stage.
He's spending his
remaining hours in Sick Bay.
Neelix...
I suppose you think
this is a fitting
punishment for me.
Maybe the Cascade
was a punishment for all of us,
for our hatred,
our brutality.
There's something
I need to tell you.
I tried to tell you
before, but...
Wha... What is it?
I want to tell you...
that I forgive you.
( sighs )
( theme playing )