( majestic theme playing )
Rust?
That's right, Captain.
High levels of ferric oxide--
corroded iron particles.
Would you mind telling me
how iron could rust in space
without oxygen?
I wish I could.
Mr. Paris,
alter our course to follow
that trail of rust.
One-quarter impulse.
Aye, Captain.
( majestic theme playing )
Captain, look at this.
I'm picking up traces
of complex hydrocarbons
in the rust--
benzene, ethylene,
acetylene...
That sounds like gasoline.
Gasoline?
It's a liquid fuel that was used
centuries ago on Earth.
They burned it to drive
internal combustion engines.
How did it get out here?
I'm detecting a small object.
It appears to be
the source of the rust
and hydrocarbons.
Put it on screen.
JANEWAY:
Magnify.
( majestic theme playing )
TUVOK:
Apparently, it is
a ground vehicle
from mid-20th-century
Earth.
Whew!
It's a 1936 Ford, actually.
Mr. Paris?
That was the manufacturing
date: 1936.
Ford was the name of
the company that built it.
Antique vehicles
are a hobby of mine.
( grunts )
( whistles )
Internal combustion engine,
a reciprocating
piston cylinder design.
Fuel source was
a refined petroleum.
Gasoline.
So, is this an early hover car?
No, you're about a century
too early for that.
This is about one step ahead
of the horse-drawn carriage.
Traces of
potassium nitrate,
ammonium and
methane back here.
I think you'll find
that's manure.
( sniffing )
Horse manure,
if I'm not mistaken.
Judging from the mud
on the wheels
and the alfalfa
seedlings
stuck in the metal frame,
I'd say this vehicle
belonged to a farmer,
or, at least, someone who
lived in a rural area.
But the question is:
How did it get here?
I doubt there are many
20th-century farmers
driving around
the Delta Quadrant.
There are no signs
of any wormholes
or temporal anomalies
in this region of space.
Let's run a metallurgical
analysis of the vehicle.
There's still oil
in the crankcase,
water in the radiator.
I wonder if the battery's
still charged.
Now, let's see.
This is before
voice-command activation,
so there should be something
in here called a key.
Key...
What are you doing?
Trying to bring this
beauty back to life.
Now, where are the keys?
Aha! Here they are.
Okay, choke out,
clutch in,
give her a little gas,
turn the key,
and step on the starter.
( starter grinding )
( engine rumbling )
( backfiring )
( sighs )
Sorry.
Next time...
you might give us
a little warning, Mr. Paris.
Aye, Captain.
I suggest we increase the
ventilation in the cargo bay
before we are asphyxiated.
What's that?
That is an amplitude modulation
receiving device.
AM radio.
I'm not sure we'll
pick up much out here.
( static hissing )
( beep )
Whoa. What was that?
( short and long beeps )
What is that?
It's too regular
to be random interference.
I'm running the signal
through the ship's database.
It's an ancient Earth
distress call known as an SOS.
I've located the source
of the SOS signal.
It's coming from a planet
in a star system
bearing 310 mark 215.
Mr. Paris, lay in a course.
Aye, Captain.
Why didn't we pick up
this signal earlier?
This isn't one of the standard
frequencies we monitor.
Messages on this channel only
travel at the speed of light--
too slow for interstellar
communications.
Course laid in, Captain.
Warp 6.
Engage.
( majestic theme playing )
CREWMAN:
I'll run a diagnostic
check, sir.
Mm-hmm.
Bring us out of warp.
Full scan, Mr. Kim.
The SOS signal is coming
from the third planet.
It's Class-L--
oxygen-argon atmosphere.
Any life signs?
There's a great deal
of trinimbic interference
in the upper atmosphere.
I can't get a clear reading
of the surface.
Can you pinpoint the coordinates
of the distress call?
Yes, here it is.
It's coming from a continent
in the northern hemisphere.
We won't be able to transport
through this kind
of interference.
I might be able to take
an away team in a shuttlecraft.
That would not be wise,
Commander,
as the atmosphere is charged
with trinimbic turbulence.
A shuttlecraft
could not safely
navigate the currents.
We could land the ship.
Are you sure that's necessary?
Someone on this planet
is sending out a distress call.
If that someone is as old
as the truck in the cargo bay,
they're long-dead by now.
This might be
an automated distress call.
Possibly.
But something brought that truck
halfway across the galaxy,
and that something
might be down on that planet.
And if it brought
the truck here,
it might be able
to take us home, too.
I'd say
it's worth a look.
Mr. Paris, prepare the ship
for landing.
Captain,
I think I should tell you,
I've never actually landed
a starship before.
That's all right, Lieutenant,
neither have I.
Bridge to Engineering.
We're going to land the ship,
Ms. Torres.
Take the warp core off-line,
vent all plasma
from the nacelles,
and stand by to engage
atmospheric thrusters.
Aye, Captain.
This is Lieutenant Tuvok
to all decks.
We are preparing
to land the ship.
Go to Blue Alert and report
to Code Blue stations.
I've plotted
a descent course.
How close do you
want to land
to the distress
coordinates?
No closer than
two kilometers.
Okay.
Atmospheric controls
at standby.
Landing mechanisms
on line.
Inertial dampers
at maximum.
TUVOK:
All decks report
Condition Blue, Captain.
Put her down, Mr. Paris.
( suspenseful theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Status.
We're on the glide trajectory.
Altitude-- 100 kilometers.
Speed-- 10,000 kph.
Encountering some trinimbic
turbulence. Compensating.
We have an EM discharge
in the lateral relays.
I'm rerouting
the ODN conduit.
Another EM discharge.
I think we're
all right, though.
20 kilometers
to the landing site.
We should be able
to see it now.
JANEWAY:
Extend landing struts.
Prepare to release
inertial dampers
and adjust them to match
the planet's gravity.
Landing struts down and locked.
Standing by
environmental controls.
Here we go.
Disengaging engines,
securing thruster exhaust.
We're down.
Not bad...for a beginner.
JANEWAY:
Nice day.
KIM:
I've locked on
to the distress signal.
It's 1.5 kilometers
on a bearing of 246.
Wait a second.
I've got something else.
There's a high concentration
of trianium particles,
bearing 225-- a little
over a kilometer away.
Looks like
some kind of power source.
Two teams.
Chakotay, yours investigates
the power source.
Tuvok, Kim,
you're with me.
My God.
TUVOK:
The metal
is an aluminum alloy.
It appears to be
an ancient Earth aircraft.
KIM:
The SOS call is
coming from inside.
I've found
the AM transmitter.
From what I can tell,
it's sending out
an automated SOS.
What about
the power source?
Somehow I find it
hard to believe
the battery on this aircraft
has been running for 400 years.
I don't recognize
the power signature.
Hold on, Captain.
I found
what appears to be
an alien fusion-based
generator.
It's hooked up to
the AM transmitter.
( on communicator ):
Chakotay to Janeway.
Go ahead, Commander.
We've located the source
of the trianium readings.
It appears to be some
sort of mine shaft.
I'd like to bring out
another security detachment
before we go inside.
Good idea. I'll join you.
Janeway out.
I want the two of you to
analyze the alien generator,
then see what you can find
out about this SOS call.
TORRES:
I'm picking up something
directly ahead.
Some kind of power signature.
Fusion-based.
TORRES:
This looks like
some kind of
cryostasis chamber.
How many bodies
are there?
Eight.
And the equipment
is still functioning.
He's human.
And from the clothes,
I'd say he's
from the same era
as the vehicle we found.
TORRES:
His life sign readings
are minimal,
but...he's alive.
Captain, according
to these readings,
there are five other
cryostasis chambers nearby.
No life signs in any of them.
This appears to be
the only one
with people inside.
There's another male over here.
This one's a female.
She's wearing
some sort of leather jacket.
And a pair of gold wings.
Wait.
There's a name tag here.
I think it's "A, period...
"E-a...
r-h-a-r-t."
"Earhart."
( whispering ):
A.... Earhart.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Amelia Earhart.
Who's Amelia Earhart?
She was one of the first
female pilots in Earth history.
In the mid-20th century,
she became quite famous
for flying across
the Atlantic Ocean.
In 1937, she attempted to fly
around the world.
According to the records
of the time,
on July 2, 1937,
Earhart and her navigator,
Fred Noonan,
took off from New Guinea,
and they were headed east
around the equator.
But somewhere in
the South Seas, they vanished,
and their disappearance
became one of the most
celebrated mysteries
of the 20th century.
Why didn't they think
she'd just crashed?
That was the most
commonly held theory.
However, numerous
searches of the area
failed to produce the wreckage
of an aircraft,
so people began to speculate.
Some thought she'd been
shot down and captured
by the Japanese navy.
Others thought that she and
Noonan had flown off together
on some sort
of romantic adventure.
Of course,
the most ridiculed notion was
that she had been...
abducted by aliens.
Well, it certainly looks
like that's what happened.
From what we can tell,
all eight of the people
in that stasis chamber
were taken from Earth
in the 1930s and brought here.
The question is: Why?
And where are the aliens
who did this?
Scans of the region
show no alien life signs.
Continue the scans.
They may not be here now,
but once they detect
our presence, they might return.
In the meantime, we'll have
to get some answers on our own.
Have you had any luck
tapping into
the computer system
in the cryo-chamber?
Not as of yet.
We are having difficulty
decoding the operating system.
There's one way
we could find out what happened.
We could wake those people up
and ask them.
I've had
the same thought myself.
Is that wise?
We don't know how these people
are going to react
when they wake up
in an alien world
in the 24th century.
JANEWAY:
True, but I'm not willing
to just leave them in stasis
for another 400 years.
And if we can find out
how they were brought here,
we might be able
to use that method to get home.
We'll just have to be very
careful how we handle this.
I suggest that only
human crew members
be present when we revive them.
Agreed.
Mr. Kim,
I want a complete analysis
of those cryostasis tubes.
Find a way
to deactivate them safely.
Aye, Captain.
Commander, apprise the Doctor
of our situation.
Tell him to instruct Kes
in the proper procedure
for reviving someone
from cryostasis.
She could be made
to look human easily enough.
In the meantime,
I suggest we all brush up
on ancient Earth.
We're about to meet
a bit of our history.
We're ready, Captain.
All the cryo-tubes
are linked
by a common
power source
so we've decided to revive
everyone simultaneously.
Proceed.
The power's off-line.
Deactivate locking mechanisms.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Captain, this one's armed
with some kind of weapon.
Disarm him,
just to be on the safe side.
( gentle theme playing )
I know this must be
very strange for you.
No...who are you?
What is going on here?
I demand you release me
immediately.
Please, if you'll just
listen for a moment,
I'll try to explain.
You are all
speaking Japanese.
Sounds to me like you're
speaking English.
It's because
of a device
we have--
a universal translator.
It allows us
to talk to each other,
even though our languages
aren't the same.
Who are you people?
Look, just let us go home.
We won't tell anybody.
The hell
we won't!
I'm going to let the world know
what you people have done.
Do you know who
you've kidnapped here?
Amelia Earhart.
I'm her navigator.
This is going
to be headline news.
You people are in trouble.
Fred...let her talk.
What I have to tell you is
going to sound hard to believe,
even preposterous.
We think you were abducted
from Earth...in the 1930s,
and brought millions
of miles through space
to a planet on the other
side of the galaxy.
You were put into a...
a kind of deep sleep
for a very long time.
It's not
the 1930s anymore.
The year is 2371--
over 400 years from
the time you were abducted.
You must think
we are awfully gullible.
JANEWAY:
Tell me,
what's the last thing
you remember
before waking up here?
We were over the Pacific,
running low on gas.
We were looking for an atoll
to set down.
We...
tried to send
out an SOS
and...
suddenly there was this...
huge light in back of us,
and the plane...
stopped dead...
and then it started moving
backward toward the light.
I must've blacked out, I...
and I w-woke up here,
just now.
That's just the way
it was with me.
I was in my truck,
heading into town.
I was just about
to get onto the blacktop
when this big light
come down from the sky--
just about blinded me.
Next thing I know,
the whole truck
was lifted up off the ground.
I believe what happened
was that you
were abducted by aliens.
And if we can find out
how they got you here,
we might all be able
to get back to Earth.
I want some real answers now.
I assure you,
I am telling the truth.
You-- come on down here
and get those, uh,
funny-looking guns of theirs.
You--
get over there
with the others.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What is this?
It's a medical device.
I'm just trying
to make sure
that everyone
is all right.
Now, how do we get out of here?
( on communicator ):
Chakotay to away team.
Janeway here.
Captain, I'm picking up
some energy displacements
on the surface.
I think it may be
alien humanoids.
It looks like they're using
some kind of deflection system
to trick our sensors.
I think you'd better get up
here.
Who's that talking?
That's Commander Chakotay,
on our ship.
Commander, huh?
Okay.
Now hear this, Commander.
There's a gun pointed
at the lady's head right now,
so you call Washington
and you tell them we're holding
your people prisoner
and they're not going anywhere
until I personally talk
to J. Edgar Hoover.
You've got one hour.
Captain?
It seems we're being
held hostage, Commander.
I suggest you pay attention
to what the gentleman says.
I understand.
Chakotay out.
All security personnel
report to the cargo bay
immediately.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The compass isn't working.
I know what we've told you
sounds hard to believe,
but there was a time
when no one believed
that a woman could fly
across the Atlantic.
Now, people are
able to travel
between the stars.
The galaxy is full
of many different species.
For instance,
this young woman
isn't human.
She's an Ocampa.
I've been on expeditions
all over the world,
and I've seen people
do all kinds of strange things
to their bodies.
That doesn't mean that Martians
have invaded Earth.
Actually,
it was the other way around.
Mars was colonized
by people from Earth in 2103.
NOONAN:
That's enough!
All of you just go over there
and sit down and keep quiet!
( suspenseful theme playing )
The trinimbic interference
has affected
the transporter's
targeting scanners.
We can't beam into the chamber,
so we'll have to go on foot.
We will deploy throughout
the caves,
sealing off any exit
from the chamber.
Let's go.
Now is probably not the
best time for that, Fred.
Just a little pick-me-up.
He's had a few nips
from that flask, Captain.
We could probably
rush him, get the gun.
Let me try to talk
to Earhart first.
She seems reasonable.
Maybe I can get
through to her.
Miss Earhart?
I want you to know
you've always been
an inspiration to me.
Because of you,
generations of women
have become pilots.
Generations?
What's your name?
Kathryn Janeway.
I heard the Commander
call you Captain.
What exactly do you captain?
The Federation Starship Voyager.
Starship?
Ha, ha. That supposed to mean
it flies through space?
That's right.
That isn't possible.
Only in books--
H.G. Wells, Jules Verne.
Maybe if you saw it, you'd think
otherwise.
Saw it?
Where is it?
On the surface.
We're actually about 100 meters
underground now.
If you'd come with me
to see Voyager,
you'd realize that what
we're telling you is true.
And risk a trap.
No, you could have hundreds
of reinforcements up there.
I assure you, we have
no interest in harming you.
We took you out of stasis
to help you.
Put yourself in my shoes,
Captain.
If you were me,
would you believe your story?
Maybe not.
Let me tell you some
of what happened
after you disappeared
over the Pacific.
No trace of you or your plane
was ever found, in spite
of a massive search.
Over the years,
there was
a lot of speculation
about your flight,
including the rumor that it was
financed by the government,
and may have been
part of an operation
to gather information
about the Japanese.
Where did you hear that?
It's somewhat common knowledge.
You see, Japan attacked
Pearl Harbor in 1941,
drawing the United States
into a massive world war.
In retrospect, your journey
was seen in a different light--
perhaps as part of
an intelligence mission
devised by a government
deeply concerned
about Japanese war plans.
No one was supposed
to know about that.
Maybe not in 1937.
Now, it's part of history.
NOONAN:
Hey, I got
an idea.
Why don't we stick them
in these things--
put them to sleep like we were?
No fuss, no trouble.
Mr. Noonan, that
will accomplish nothing.
Please, let us take you
to our ship.
You'll see that everything
we've told you is true.
Show me how to
operate this thing.
Hey, last time I looked,
you were working for me...
and I think we should listen
to these people.
They just may
be telling the truth.
What's the harm in seeing
if maybe they do have
this starship?
It beats being cooped up
in here
trying to figure out
what happened.
( sighs heavily )
How about it?
Anyone want to come along?
Hey, I wouldn't
mind taking a look.
Anyone else?
You're not
leaving me behind.
Kes and I will stay with
the others, Captain.
It'll take about ten minutes
to get to the surface.
Stay close to us.
Mr. Kim.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What is it?
I am reading energy
displacements again--
possibly alien life signs--
200 meters ahead.
They may be up there.
Take cover!
Get down!
( shouting )
( dramatic theme swelling )
( suspenseful theme playing )
This way.
( distant weapons fire )
What's all
that racket?
Take cover!
I told you it was a trick!
Aah! Unh!
Fred!
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunting )
Janeway to Chakotay.
( on communicator ):
I'm here, Captain.
We're pinned down.
I can see you from here.
Lay down phaser fire.
I'm going to circle around
to your left.
Try to come at them
from the rear.
Right!
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
Chakotay to Voyager.
Torres here, Commander.
Can you give us
some help down here?
I don't think so.
The targeting scanners
are still useless.
I can't risk laying down
weapons fire
if I don't know
where it's going.
Keeping trying
to get them on line!
Aye, Commander.
( grunts )
Hold your fire.
Drop your weapons.
Turn around slowly.
You're not Briori.
No, I'm human.
Human?
We're human.
You're working
for the Briori.
They have ships
like yours.
I'll answer any questions
you have,
but first, we must take care
of our wounded.
Can we agree to end this?
Yes.
( man moans )
I'm Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
John Evansville.
This is my colleague,
Karyn Berlin.
Severe trauma
to the thoracic cavity,
lacerated carotid artery.
He's not
going to make it.
I wouldn't be
so sure of that.
Vascular regenerator.
Hmm...
he's not responding
to the treatment.
The alcohol level in his blood
is so high, it's inhibiting
the repair to his
circulatory system.
Attempting to compensate.
I told you your drinking'd
kill you one day.
She's right, Doc.
Just let me die in peace.
There's just one thing
I want to say to you first...
...even though
it's 400 years late.
Amelia...
I love you.
Fred...
you never said anything.
You're married--
or you were.
I guess he's dead now.
I just wanted you to know
before...
before I met my Maker.
There. That should do it.
Do what?
You're healed.
You mean, I'm not going to die?
Aside from a hangover,
you're going to be fine.
Oh, Amelia, you, uh...
...you got to forget
what I just told you.
Promise me.
Fred, I already have.
Oh...
You've taken the 37's.
Why?
I'm afraid
I don't understand.
You went
into the shrine.
You stole the 37's
from the sacred altars
and you disturbed
the radio signal
that we have been so careful
to preserve.
Captain, I think he's talking
about Earhart
and the others.
Tell me more about the 37's.
Are you one of them?
I'm one of their descendants.
The 37's were brought here
over 15 generations ago
by the Briori.
Who are the Briori?
They're an alien race.
They abducted over 300 people
from Earth in the year 1937.
Brought them over here,
turned them into slaves.
But those slaves revolted,
killed the Briori,
took their weapons
and their technology
and survived.
And now,
there are over 100,000 of us.
( wry laugh )
The Briori never came back.
Now, you answer me.
Why did you steal
the remaining 37's
from the shrine?
We didn't steal them,
we simply revived them.
Revived them?
They're dead.
No, they were simply
in a state of what
we call "cryostasis."
That's a form of sleep
that appears very
much like death.
Do you mean they're alive?
Yes.
My people have come to regard
the 37's as monuments
to our ancestors.
Nobody has even entered
their shrine for generations.
Mr. Evansville,
we were hoping
to find the ship that brought
your ancestors here--
possibly use it to get back
to Earth a little faster.
I'm sorry.
The Briori ship was destroyed
in the slave revolt.
There's nothing left.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Captain...
I'm sorry to hear
about your long journey home.
But you should know that life
on this planet is good.
We live in three
beautiful cities
only 50 miles from here.
Oh, I'd like to see your cities.
And I'd like
to show them to you.
How fast?
Warp 9.9.
In your terms, that's about
four billion miles
a second.
Think I could take her out
for a spin?
Well, uh...ha.
Mr. Evansville has offered
to take us on a tour
of the settlements.
He's extended the invitation
to the entire crew.
And the 37's, of course.
You...?
You're a 37?
( gentle theme playing )
I guess you could call me that.
It would be
an honor to show you our cities.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48975.1.
Evansville wasn't exaggerating
when he said they have
a lot to be proud of here.
It was an amazing experience,
but it's left me
a little disturbed.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Here's the damage report
you asked for.
Thank you.
Is something wrong, Captain?
You've seemed
a little
distracted ever since
we came back from the cities.
Weren't you impressed?
A little too impressed.
What do you mean?
JANEWAY:
There's a thriving
sophisticated culture on
this planet-- of human beings.
In some ways,
walking around those cities
was...almost like being
back on Earth.
It was a little eerie.
It reminded me of home, too.
Evansville has offered to
let any of our crew stay.
What will you do about that?
Maybe this is
one of those decisions
that the Captain has to make
for the entire ship.
You may have a problem
if a lot of people want to stay.
I know that. But at the same
time, I can't take a vote
every time there's
a major decision to be made.
And yet...
we're a long way from Starfleet.
And a lot of the rules
and regulations
I've learned to uphold
seem distant, as well.
Am I the only one who is
so intent on getting home?
Is it just me?
Am I leading the crew
on a forlorn mission,
with...no real hope of success?
You're not alone.
I want to get home, too.
And there's not a day
that goes by
when I don't hear someone
mention Earth.
The people here have built
a new Earth.
We could stay,
help them build
a human civilization
in the Delta Quadrant.
Isn't that an exciting prospect?
Shouldn't we be grateful
for the opportunity
they're giving us?
It is a tempting prospect.
But when I hold it up
against the prospect
of seeing the sunrise
over the Arizona desert
or swimming in the Gulf
of Mexico on a summer's day,
there's just no comparison.
I want to go home.
We have 152 men and women
on this ship.
What happens if half of them
decide to stay on the planet?
Could we operate Voyager
with 75 crew members?
I doubt it.
In fact, I don't think
we could operate the ship
with fewer than 100.
If too many of the crew
choose to stay behind...
we could all be stranded here.
( sighs )
Tell all hands to prepare for
an announcement from the Captain
at 1400 hours.
They deserve to make the choice
for themselves.
Aye, Captain.
( majestic theme builds
and swells )
( door opens and closes )
( gentle theme playing )
Here we are.
My research on 20th century
Earth is a little thin,
but I've done what I can.
Pot roast, green beans
and something called...
Jell...O.
You know how to make Jell-O?
I even put in fruit cocktail.
NOONAN:
You don't say.
MAN:
I don't know
about the rest of you,
but I've made up my mind.
There is land here
that goes begging,
and I could have a big farm,
just like
I always dreamed.
And for you, rice,
with a little fish.
I even replicated some
ginger for seasoning.
Very nice. Thank you.
Yeah, I have to admit--
life here looks a lot better
than what we left on Earth.
It's a paradise by comparison.
And there are
many Japanese here.
I could be very happy.
We all could.
Right?
( sighs )
I'm just not sure, I...
What about you, Mr. Neelix?
Have you made your decision?
Oh, yes, indeed.
I'm staying right here
with Captain Janeway.
She'd be lost without me.
She's come to depend on me
a great deal.
What about the rest of the crew?
You think many of them
will stay here?
Oh, I don't think so.
At least, not many.
Uh, well, that is,
there's a good chance...
Well, now that you ask,
I honestly don't know.
You? You'd stay here
on the planet?
I didn't say
I was going to.
I just said
I could understand
why people would want to.
The people here
remind me of home.
I haven't felt like that
since I left Earth.
But-- But you're Starfleet.
You've always wanted
a life in space.
I know,
but...my whole life?
On a starship, day after day,
with no end in sight?
That's not exactly
what I had in mind.
You're not the first person
I've heard talk like this.
A lot of people
are thinking about staying.
What about you?
Don't you have
some of those feelings?
I'd be lying if I said I didn't.
( gentle theme playing )
Captain.
I was told
I'd find you here.
Am I intruding?
Not at all. Please join me.
I wanted you
to know that
the group you brought
out of stasis--
we've all decided to stay here
on the planet.
( sighs )
I understand.
I must admit, the thought
of traveling through space--
maybe even learning
to fly this ship--
was very appealing to me.
And I'd looked forward
to getting to
know you better.
I suspect we have
a lot in common.
At first,
I didn't know what to do.
We talked about it
for quite some time.
Finally, I realized
the people here on this planet
are part of us.
We're their ancestors,
in a way.
Well, it made us
feel close to them.
The remarkable thing about
the humans on this planet
is that they evolved very much
like the people on Earth.
Tens of thousands
of light-years apart,
both civilizations
managed to create a world
they could be proud of--
one where war and poverty
simply don't exist.
I certainly can't blame you
for wanting to be part of it,
any more than I can blame
members of my crew
if they make the same decision.
When will you find out?
In half an hour.
Anyone who wants
to stay behind
is to report to the
cargo bay at 1500 hours.
I expect Jarvin will
stay on the planet.
In fact, I'd bet on it.
Why Jarvin?
He's been more
uncomfortable
about being on
a Starfleet ship
than most of the Maquis.
And he's gotten involved
with a young woman
in Quantum Mechanics.
I think they'd like to
settle down, raise a family.
The person I expect
to see is Baxter.
Baxter?
Walter Baxter?
He's adventurous,
a risk-taker.
I can see him wanting
to take on the challenge
of building a new life
on this planet.
I'd hate to lose Baxter.
He's a good man.
I'd hate to lose Jarvin.
I don't want to lose anyone.
We've all been through
so much together,
it just wouldn't
seem right.
But I couldn't
blame anyone--
anyone-- for staying behind.
I'm not sure
I want to go in.
No matter what happens,
we'll make it.
Remember that.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )
TUVOK:
Captain on the Bridge.
All stations,
prepare for departure.
Condition Blue, Mr. Tuvok.
Ms. Torres,
antigrav thrusters on line.
Thrusters enabled.
Mr. Paris, inertial dampers
to flight configuration.
Impulse drive to standby.
Yes, ma'am.
KIM:
All stations report
ready, Captain.
Then let's do it.
Take us up.
( dramatic theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )