CHAKOTAY:
First officer's personal log,
stardate 49005.3.
The captain has granted me
the use of a shuttlecraft
so that I may
perform the Pakra--
a solitary ritual
commemorating the anniversary
of my father's death.
A-koo-chee-moya.
I pray on this day of memories
to speak to my father--
the one whom the wind
called Kolopak.
Though I am far from his bones,
perhaps there is a spirit
in these unnamed skies
who will find him
and honor him with my song.
A-koo-chee-moya.
There. You see?
We should teach
them the price
of displaying their
markings in our space.
I'll go.
Let Kar do it this time.
He's not ready.
He thinks he is.
He's been demanding
a chance for weeks
to earn his name.
Do you really believe
he could do this?
Can you honestly say
you knew you were ready
for your first mission,
Haliz?
Tell him. Tell him
today's the day
he will finally
be called Ogla.
( phasers blasting )
COMPUTER:
The shuttlecraft
has sustained phaser fire.
Minor damage to aft shields.
Source?
A Kazon spacecraft,
closing at 195, mark 6.
Computer, open a channel
to the Kazon vessel.
This is Commander Chakotay
of the Federation
starship Voyager.
Why have you fired on me?
You are in Kazon-Ogla space,
Federation.
I wasn't aware of that.
I have no hostile intentions.
Power down your weapons
and I'll leave.
No one who violates
Ogla space leaves.
Look, son, my starship is only
a few light years away.
I am not your son,
Federation.
I am your executioner.
( phasers blasting )
Chakotay to Kazon vessel.
Listen carefully.
I do not want a fight.
Stand down, or I'll be
forced to return fire.
( phasers blasting )
Chakotay to Kazon vessel.
I have established
a direct weapons lock
on your engine core.
This is my final warning.
If you don't stand down,
I will destroy your ship.
All right.
If that's the way
you want to play it.
Chakotay to Kazon vessel.
Do you read me?
Computer,
are there any life signs
inside the Kazon vessel?
Affirmative. One life sign.
Kazon ship,
your engine core is critical.
You have less than 30 seconds to
evacuate.
Do you read me?
If you have an escape pod,
you must eject now.
Computer, establish
a transporter lock
on the life-form.
Acknowledged.
Targeting scanners.
Prepare to beam him aboard.
Scanners locked.
Energize.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Computer, damage report.
Long-range communications,
lateral sensor array
and aft shields are off-line.
Great!
Welcome aboard.
It's not that I feel
that i'm not
making contributions
as chef and morale officer.
You're making significant
contributions, Neelix.
Well, if you insist, but...
I can't imagine how
Lieutenant Ayala
would be handling
the separation
from his children
without you.
He misses his boys terribly.
I wish I could do more for him.
And your meals
are getting to be...
yes?
Almost certainly...
a highlight of every day.
Oh, Captain!
You always know
how to touch one's heart.
Thank you.
When I signed on
I promised you that...
I promised you
that I would stand by your side
through every danger
this quadrant has to offer--
as guide,
as strategist
as explorer,
as adventurer...
Yes?
I feel...
under-utilized.
I can swashbuckle
with the best of them.
You weren't invited
to the holodeck defense
simulations, were you?
No!
TUVOK:
Captain, you are needed
on the bridge.
On my way. I'll see to it
you're invited next time.
And now, Mr. Neelix, please--
join me on the bridge.
Yes, sir...
ma'am... captain.
We are ready to depart.
However, Commander Chakotay
has still not returned.
Have you tried
hailing him?
On all frequencies,
no response.
When was the last time
we heard from him?
More than six hours ago.
Well, according to
his flight plan
he's not far.
We'll just have
to go get him.
I want all away teams
back on board now.
Mr. Paris,
plot a course
for Chakotay's
last known coordinates.
Aye, captain.
( grunting )
What am I doing here?
You're welcome.
What?
It's a human expression.
You thank me for
saving your life
I say, "you're welcome."
( yelling )
I accept your surrender.
Look! I promise you,
as soon
as we get back to Voyager
we'll find a Kazon ship
and hand you over them.
You should have let me die.
I'm not in the habit
of killing children.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Alien vessel
approaching at 022 mark 8.
What's your name, son?
What?
Your name?
Why do you want
to know my name?
I want to let them know
you're on board.
I'm called Kar.
Computer open
a channel.
Kazon vessel, I have a young man
on board you might know.
He goes by the name of Kar.
I'd say
he's about 13.
I'd like to arrange
for his transfer
before I return to my ship.
Computer, confirm
channel is open.
Confirmed.
Transmission has been received.
Talk to them.
Tell them you're okay.
Warning. Kazon vessel
has engaged a tractor beam.
Full reverse.
Unable to comply.
Tractor force exceeds
available engine power.
They're pulling us in.
Kill me.
Please!
Why are you so eager
for me to kill you?
Because there are worse things
than being killed by your enemy.
CHAKOTAY:
Look, if you check your
long-range sensors.
You'll find a big ship
out there.
It's called Voyager, and by now,
it's on its way to find me.
Kar. I told Razik
you weren't ready.
I have a fair idea
of why I'm here
but why are they
doing this to you?
I was ready, Haliz.
Ready to kill or die.
I felt the flames
touch my skin.
Go back in, Kar.
It was this fool.
This... Federation,
who doesn't even have
the courage to kill
his enemies.
He pulled me out
with that transporter
we've heard about.
Like the Nistrim
and Relora before you...
you come into our space,
showing off your uniforms
and displaying the markings
of your Federation
with no respect
as if you own
this part of space.
But it belongs to us!
I tried to kill him Haliz!
( grunts )
( weapon cocking )
I want to see Razik.
Tell Razik
I demand to see him.
Who's Razik?
You tell this Razik
that Federation Commander
Chakotay demands to see him.
What are you doing?
Razik is obviously your leader.
I'm hoping if he's strong
enough to be in command
he's wise enough
to listen to reason.
( laughing )
You see this?
This is debris
from a Nistrim frigate.
The man you are demanding
to see destroyed it
killing more than 100
in a single shot.
Before that, his
name was only Ra.
Now he is called Jal Razik.
And this tunic belonged
to a Relora warrior.
He was killed
by the bare hands
of another Ogla,
called only Hali.
Now that man is
called Jal Haliz
one of our
greatest fighters.
And this bracelet belonged
to the man
who killed my brother.
My brother, Jal Kinell...
who earned his Ogla name
by dying bravely in battle
but I... I will never earn
my name in life or in death
and I have you
to thank for that.
We're approaching Chakotay's
last known coordinates, captain.
All stop.
Full sensor scan, Mr. Kim.
I'm picking up
floating debris
composed of
duranium, magnesite
and electroceramics.
Also heavy traces
of carbon residue.
Bridge to
engineering.
Prepare to receive debris
samples for analysis.
TORRES:
Aye, captain.
Transport complete.
Captain, I am detecting
an ion trail leading away
from this location.
Chakotay's shuttle?
The signature of the radiation
is not consistent
with Federation
propulsion systems.
PARIS:
So what are we saying here?
That someone blew up Chakotay's
shuttle and then took off?
That's speculation, Mr. Paris
but that trail's
the only clue we have
to Chakotay's
whereabouts.
Laying in a course.
Engage.
Hello, Kar.
I never thought
I would see you like this.
It was not my fault.
It was his technology.
Don't make excuses, Kar.
An Ogla has no room
for excuses.
No. No excuses.
I forgive you.
Know that in your heart.
No, please...
( anguished moan )
RAZIK:
You will eat
at my right hand tonight.
Why did you save him?
It's a very ineffective
way of waging war.
I'm not at war with you.
I wish I could
say the same.
We're not familiar
with this part of space.
If I'd seen a map identifying
this as Kazon-Ogla territory
I wouldn't have been
anywhere near it.
Unfortunately our territorial
claims change every day.
Maps do not
serve us well.
You did him a great disservice,
you know.
I guess if he
had killed me
my uniform would have made
you all a fine trophy.
Your uniform may yet
decorate our wall.
You may not think
you're at war with us,
Federation Commander Chakotay
but everything you are
is a threat to us.
The Kazon fought long and hard
for their independence
from uniforms like yours.
Uniforms, maybe,
but not like mine.
Your uniforms, your laws,
your technology.
You are not welcome here.
Get him something to eat.
The execution is tonight.
JANEWAY:
Well?
Most of the debris
we've examined
is composed of
a polyduranide alloy
which isn't used
in the construction
of Federation spacecraft.
So it wasn't Chakotay's
shuttle that was destroyed.
This ship was Kazon.
You get them
involved young, Haliz.
As soon as
they're old enough
to protect their
younger siblings.
So they brought you here
to see your first human.
Take a good look--
you won't see
any hate in my eyes.
I'm a gentle man
from a gentle people
who wish you no harm.
RAZIK:
That's enough!
I know you'd like them
to hate me, Razik, but I want
their first impression
of humans to be a good one.
You've been brought here
to learn what it means
to be a Kazon male.
You all know Kar.
You've learned
to fight together
haven't you?
Kar was sent
to kill this man
to earn his Ogla name
but Kar failed
and will not earn his name
even in death.
Who would be willing
to kill the human?
So much for first impressions,
Federation.
I'm proud of you.
Each will get
your chance someday.
But that's not what
we're here for today.
We are here to learn
the price of failure in battle.
Take it.
What for?
So you can kill Kar as you
should have done in battle.
You want me to kill a child
in front of other children.
What would it accomplish?
It will teach these little boys
an important lesson.
And after you do that,
you'll be free to go.
You may think
I want your friend Kar to die
but you'd be wrong.
I've seen too many Ogla die
at the hands of our enemies.
That is why
you must learn there are
no second chances in battle.
That is why Kar must die.
If I refuse?
( weapons cocking )
I'll be needing
my shuttle back.
Do you really think
you can escape us
in the little vessel of yours?
That's a chance
I'm willing to take.
What about you?
Let the coward run.
Prepare his shuttle.
Want to come?
There doesn't seem
to be much of a future
for you here.
He'd rather die than run
like a Calogan dog with you,
Federation.
If I stay here,
I'll die without a name
and Razik taught me only cowards
die without a name.
You won't find your name running
after the Federation, Kar.
Maybe not, but that's a chance
I'm willing to take.
I'll show you how to disable
the weapons system.
Will Razik
be all right?
Don't worry.
He's only stunned.
( weapons blasting )
Didn't take them long
to get those weapons
back on line, did it?
Computer,
prepare to go to warp.
No. Their ship is much
clumsier at lower speeds.
We should try
to outmaneuver them.
You're the boss.
Initiate evasive pattern
theta two. Full impulse.
I can give you
the shield frequencies
of their ship.
We can hit them
back easily.
It may mean something to you
to die a violent death
but I'd like to get out of this
without killing
or being killed.
You'd rather die in your
sleep a wrinkled old man?
Sounds about right.
Computer, damage report.
Aft shields at 63%.
We're not going
to make it like this.
Computer, scan for
an M-Class atmosphere.
There is an M-Class moon
at bearing 108, mark 18.
Distance 1.9 million kilometers.
That's Tarok.
Where the Ogla conduct
training exercises.
Anybody training
there now?
Computer, lay in a course
to the moon.
Evasive pattern omega one.
Maximum impulse.
Warning: aft shields
have been penetrated.
Computer, prepare
for long-range transport.
Two to beam to the surface.
Transport is not recommended.
The moon is out
of safety range.
TUVOK:
Captain, the ion trail
is beginning to dissipate.
All stop.
KIM:
I'm picking up debris again.
More duranium, magnesite,
carbon residue...
it's the remnants
of another ship.
Bridge to engineering.
Lieutenant Torres, prepare to
receive another debris sample.
TORRES:
Acknowledged.
KIM:
Transport underway.
[TRANSPORTERS SOUNDING]
Torres to bridge.
Sample received.
JANEWAY:
Let me know when you've
got something, B'Elanna.
I've got something right now.
It's a piece
of Chakotay's shuttle.
( sighs )
( groaning )
Kar...
It worked?
The computer said the transport
wasn't recommended.
Didn't say
it was impossible.
With any luck
Razik will think we
didn't survive the explosion
then maybe you'll get your
name for dying in battle.
In battle?!
That wasn't a battle!
We didn't even
shoot back.
And now I'm stranded here.
With you.
Yes, you're stranded
here with me
and I'm stranded here with you
because for some reason
that escapes me at the moment
I keep saving your life.
Now if you want to
hate me for that, fine.
But I'd really appreciate it
if you kept it to yourself.
You...
To yourself!
First thing we've got
to do is find some shelter
and get out of this heat.
Any suggestions?
I think we're
finally beginning
to understand each other.
You don't know
what you're doing.
What did I just say?
Get down.
What the hell was that?
A proton beam.
They're hidden
everywhere
along with biomagnetic traps
and disrupter snares.
Charming.
I told you.
The Ogla train
on this moon.
I was here myself
last year...
with Razik.
So I guess you know
your way around.
I know that you're
in my territory
and if you want to live to
become that wrinkled old man
you' going to have
to do what I say.
Well, it looks like
you just saved my life.
Twice more and we'll be even.
I've finished analyzing
the shuttle debris
and I found no evidence
of human remains.
Then it's possible Chakotay
wasn't killed in the explosion.
That is correct.
That's the first good news
I've heard all day.
Thank you, doctor.
My pleasure.
Now, would you mind having
someone transport this junk
to the cargo bay.
It's cluttering up my lab.
JANEWAY:
Of course, doctor.
All right then. If commander
Chakotay wasn't in the shuttle,
where is he?
From the dispersal
pattern of the debris
we've been able to extrapolate
Chakotay's course
prior to the explosion.
It appears
he was heading
for an M-Class moon
in this system.
And we found a resual
energy displacement
within the debris field
that isn't consistent
with the explosion itself.
You think he transported
to that moon.
We tried to scan
the surface
but there is intense
radiothermic interference.
Radiothermic?
It appears to be coming from
subterranean energy sources--
several carefully hidden
weapons systems--
phaser banks, force fields,
proton dischargers.
KES:
Kazon.
When they captured me I saw how
they concealed their weaponry.
I believe you call them
"booby traps."
then this moon is some kind
of Kazon fortification.
Or it may simply be
a training site.
For the Kazon,
live ammunition
is a very effective
teaching tool.
In the absence
of evidence to the contrary
I choose to believe
Chakotay made it to that moon.
Mr. Kim,
see if you can determine
the most probable location
he would've beamed to.
Lieutenant, you and I
will lead the away team.
As you wish, captain,
but I must point out
that due to radiothermic
interference,
we will not be communicate
able to with the ship.
I'm already working
on a dampening field
to cut through
the interference
but it'll take
several hours, at least.
I don't want to wait
that long, but keep trying.
Neelix, Kes, you are
our two Kazon experts.
Kes, you'll come
with Tuvok and me.
Neelix, you said
you wanted more to do.
Well, now's your chance.
I want you on the bridge
with Mr. Paris
in case we run into
any Kazon ships.
Don't worry, captain.
You can count on me
to keep those
nefarious Kazon at bay.
Dismissed.
What are you doing?
I'm setting my tricorder
to emit a homing signal.
What for?
So when my people show up
they'll know where
to look for me.
They won't come.
They'll think
you're dead.
They're very persistent.
I'm betting
they haven't given up on me.
Maybe I should kill you
and steal your technology
and deliver it to my people.
Then they'd have
to give me my name.
You just won't give up,
will you?
You won't stop me from earning
my name, Federation.
Not Federation.
Chakotay.
That's my name.
( tricorder beeping )
Did you have to earn it?
No. Not exactly.
Then your name means nothing.
My name was a gift...
from my tribe.
I cherish it
every day of my life
just as I cherish
the Federation uniform.
I should respect you
because you wear that uniform.
Your name,
my uniform--
not much difference.
We both have
to earn them.
What did you have to do
to earn your uniform?
Study.
Years of study.
Learning about science
and ships and navigation.
I suppose they don't expect you
to prove your battle skills.
No. They prepared us to
defend ourselves in battle.
They prepared
us very well
and we had to pass
many difficult tests
before we were given the
right to wear the uniform.
You're saying that my
name and your uniform
mean the same thing,
but you're wrong.
Why?
What's so different
about us?
Aside from the fact that
I keep saving your life
and you keep threatening
to kill me?
I must protect
my territory.
Territory is power.
Let me tell
you something.
I have no interest in your
territory or anybody else's.
My people taught me
a man does not own land.
He doesn't own anything
but the courage and
loyalty in his heart.
That's where my
power comes from.
I think we both could use
some sleep, don't you?
( soft beeping )
( beeping )
I've got a Kazon
raider approaching
at bearing 288 mark 9.
On screen.
Open a channel.
I'm lieutenant Tom Paris
of the starship Voyager.
Jal Razik, first Maje
of the Kazon-Ogla.
I will speak to your captain.
I'm in command right now,
so you can speak to me.
You are trespassing
in Ogla space.
Why do you orbit our moon?
Just stopped to make
a few repairs.
We'll be on our way in no time.
That is a lie.
You are looking for
your Commander Chakotay.
Now, how would
you know about that?
Quite simply
we killed him.
Under what circumstances?
He kidnapped a young man.
During his escape
it became necessary
to destroy his ship.
No doubt you've
found the remains.
So I suggest you depart
immediately.
Thanks for the advice.
NEELIX:
What a most
unusual offer.
A Kazon-Ogla Maje
allowing a trespasser
to leave his space unharmed.
What would the other Kazon
say about
this new merciful attitude
of the Ogla?
Don't tempt me, Talaxian.
I would just as soon open fire.
NEELIX:
Would you?
Neelix...
No, I don't think so.
That would attract
every rival Kazon sect
to your secret training base,
wouldn't it?
Now, I know
your ships, Maje.
I even sold a few plaxan sensors
to the Ogla a few years back.
I have no doubt
that you read
the same life signs
on that moon that we have.
Perhaps one of those life signs
belongs to your captain.
If you've detected
the extensive weaponry
deployed on the moon,
know this:
With one remote command,
I can cause that weaponry
to self-destruct,
destroying the surface
of the moon
and everyone on it.
Neither of us wants that, do we?
Think of the cost of replacing
all those weapons.
Awfully hard to come by
in this region.
And it would make you
so vulnerable to your enemies.
PARIS:
We'll leave
as soon as we've retrieved
our crewmen-- all of them
including Chakotay,
if he's alive.
And if one of your people
is with him
he'll be returned to you.
KIM:
They're moving
into a lower orbit
looks like they're intending to
enter the atmosphere.
I need communication with
the surface, B'Elanna and soon.
I still haven't been able to get
the dampening field working.
I can't even give you
an estimate.
Should we take Voyager down?
I've already run
a soil analysis.
The surface won't support
a landing.
Then I guess the captain's
going to be greeted
by some unexpected visitors.
At least
we bought her some time.
Good morning.
How did you sleep?
Fine.
Really?
You seemed a little
restless to me.
What do you mean?
All that skulking around
throwing things.
You were awake?
You think I'm going
to get much sleep
around an Ogla warrior who's
threatened to kill me?
Why didn't you
go through with it?
I am a coward.
I don't believe that.
I don't believe you do, either.
I think maybe you're beginning
to realize I'm not your enemy
and only a fool
would kill a friend.
If you are my friend...
then you're my only one.
What happens to me now?
Where do I go?
Would any other Kazon sect
accept you?
I would be a goven,
an outcast.
Each Kazon sect I meet
would cut one digit off
and send me away.
How many Kazon sects
are there?
It changes every day.
Yesterday there were 18.
I guess you could
come with us.
To do what?
Dress in a uniform?
You wouldn't have
to wear a uniform.
And the closer you'd get
to your home
the farther I would be
from mine.
If only you had killed me.
Captain, four life-forms
approaching.
40 meters.
They appear to be Kazon.
Please, put your weapons away.
We've come to help you.
Help us? With what?
We made contact
with your ship
and learned of the plight of
your missing crewman.
We've come to offer our
assistance in finding him.
That's very kind of you.
You're walking
on dangerous ground.
There are concealed
weapons everywhere.
Come. We will lead
you through them.
Very well.
Tell me about
the other uniforms--
the ones the
Kazons fought.
The trabe.
The Kazon
shared their homeworld
if you can call it sharing.
They had everything;
We had nothing--
until we took it from them
in the revolt 26 years ago.
( tricorder beeps )
What is it?
People coming this way.
Humans and Kazon.
What are we going to do?
There's only one way back
to the Ogla for you
and that's if you
earn your name.
So I guess that's what
you'll have to do.
But how?
You're going to
have to kill me.
The signal seems to be coming
from some caves
approximately 40 meters ahead.
Your technology
continues to amaze us.
It would have taken us
weeks to track them.
After this is over,
we have to discuss an alliance.
JANEWAY:
I would welcome
your friendship, Maje.
Captain Janeway, I'm reading
elevated radiothermic
levels here.
The Ocampa female is correct.
This is a particularly
dangerous place.
We lose many trainees here.
Perhaps you would prefer
if we preeded alone.
They can't be far now.
Thanks, but I think
we'll stick together.
PARIS:
Voyager to away team.
We're here, Mr. Paris.
We finally broke through
the interference, captain.
Are you all right?
We had a run-in...
Everything is fine. We have
the assistance of the Ogla.
That's what I was going
to tell you to expect.
Can you lock on
to Commander Chakotay?
Stand by.
Voyager to Chakotay,
do you read?
CHAKOTAY:
I'm fine, Paris.
Stand by for us
to beam you out of there.
Belay that, Voyager. Stand by.
According to my readings
the away team's
only 50 meters away.
Right, but...
and alert sick bay
for a code white resuscitation.
Did you say "code white"?
Correct.
I don't have time
to explain now.
Chakotay out.
It'll be alright.
Our technology can revive me
even if I'm brain-dead
for two minutes.
Why are you doing this?
Like you said it's my fault
you don't have your name.
I can't leave you
behind like this.
Chakotay to away team.
Good to hear your
voice, commander.
Captain, proceed with caution.
I have been taken prisoner
by a young Kazon.
He's threaning to kill me.
This way.
It's safer.
I would beg to differ.
Based on these readings
that way would seem
the logical choice.
I must apologize
for my comrade.
I believe he's trying
to mislead you.
So your technology
is not always an ally.
Sometimes it
betrays you. Pity.
I'm afraid
you would not score well
on our training exercises.
Away team to Voyager.
KES:
Captain, that panel
is a micro-generator.
JANEWAY:
You're right. If we
can get a narrow beam
through the field,
we can disable it.
We could try remodulating
the phasers
to a higher-
frequency output.
Make it fast.
I've been waiting
for you, Razik.
RAZIK:
So, the Federation commander
is your prisoner.
I only came with him
so I could have another
chance to kill him.
So you could earn your name.
That's what
I've been hoping for, Razik.
But you taught me well.
I know what you're going to say.
You've said it
so many times before.
In battle there are
no second chances.
But you are not my enemy.
He is.
( groans )
My name is Jal Karden,
Kazon-Ogla.
You are first Maje
now, Haliz.
My life is yours.
Kill me if you wish
or let me live and I will
follow you into battle
whenever you command.
Jal Karden.
Kazon-Ogla.
The Federation
does not belong here.
If we meet again,
I will not hesitate to kill you.
I understand.
Janeway to Voyager.
Five to beam up.
A-koo-chee-moya.
I pray on this day of memories
to speak to my father
the one whom the wind
called Kolopak.
Father, if you can hear me
among these unnamed stars
I ask you to continue
to watch over me
as you've always done.
I ask you also to watch over
a boy called Karden
who has a difficult path
to travel.
A-koo-chee-moya.