Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Hello?
( sighs )
Computer, who activated
the emergency medical
holographic program?
COMPUTER:
Auto-initiation
of the EMH program
occurred when a shipwide
Red Alert was initiated.
Emergency?
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Captain Janeway, please respond.
Captain Janeway
is not on board the ship.
Well, then, who's in command?
Internal scans indicate
no crew members are on board.
You mean, the ship's empty?
Affirmative.
What is
the crew's current location?
Unknown.
Did they go on shore leave?
Are they dead? What?
That information
is not available.
Can you give me
a ship's status report?
Affirmative.
Warp core is off-line.
The ship is restricted
to emergency power
and auxiliary systems only.
Structural integrity breach
on Deck 6, Deck 7 and Deck 12.
Deflector shields inoperative.
Weapons array off-line.
Communications off-line.
Sewage and waste reclamation...
All right, I get the idea.
What caused this damage?
That information
is not available.
Of course it isn't.
Computer, transfer all
Bridge logs to this station.
Accessing Bridge logs.
Replay last log entry.
Heavy casualties...
the warp core's going critical
and the ejection system
is off-line.
I've ordered all personnel
to abandon ship.
Lieutenant Torres and I...
Computer, have any escape pods
been ejected?
All escape pods
were launched at 2100 hours.
Scan the ship
for any humanoid life-forms.
There are no humanoid
life-forms aboard this vessel.
Well, I'm glad everyone bothered
to say good-bye.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
Stardate 48892.1.
It appears that Voyager
has suffered a... disaster.
What kind I don't know,
but one thing is clear.
The crew was forced
to abandon ship.
It would therefore seem
that my usefulness
has come to an end.
I am terminating my program.
If anyone finds this Log,
I can be reactivated by...
( thumping )
Hello?!
( thumping, clattering )
( pounding )
Hello?!
( panting )
Doctor!
What are you doing?!
Sorry. I wasn't expecting
a member of the crew.
The computer said
everyone had left.
The internal sensors
were damaged during the attack.
They must not be reading
every life sign on the ship.
Attack?
The Kazon.
Two of their Predator-class
warships took us by surprise,
hit us with a volley
of plasma torpedoes.
It started a core breach,
and we had to abandon ship.
The Captain and I
stayed behind
to see if we could
stop the breach.
At the last second, we did.
Why didn't the crew
return to the ship?
Because they couldn't.
The Kazon tractored
all the life pods
onto their ships.
They went into warp
before we could stop them.
What's wrong?
This tricorder isn't
registering your life signs.
This one isn't working either.
( groans )
You've got to help
the Captain.
She was hit
by a falling support beam.
I didn't want
to risk moving her,
so I had to leave her
on the Bridge.
Can't we beam her
to Sick Bay?
Transporters are down,
so are the turbolifts.
I had to crawl through
31 Jefferies tubes
on five decks to get here.
Then you're going to have to
go back
with a medical kit.
I'll instruct you on how--
You don't understand.
I'm not going.
You are.
I'm sending you
to the Bridge.
That would be ideal
if it were possible,
but my projection
system is limited
to the Sick Bay
and the holodecks.
Not anymore.
For the past few weeks,
we've been setting up
holographic emitters
on critical decks.
We were hoping to set up
a remote holo-projection system,
give you access
to other parts of the ship.
Why wasn't I told
about this?
We hadn't even tested
the system yet.
There was no guarantee
it was going to work.
I guess the Captain didn't want
to get your hopes up.
Her compassion
is heartwarming.
But next time, I'd rather
be kept informed.
Where are these
remote projectors?
Decks 1 through 5.
We also put them in Engineering,
the Mess Hall and the Cargo Bay.
All the projectors
are in place,
but the problem is, we're
going to have to interface
with the Sick Bay
imaging system.
That's going to take a lot
of power and computer memory.
I don't know if we have
enough reserve power to spare.
Most of the crew is gone.
Could we divert power
from life support systems?
Good idea.
I can drop
life support down
to minimum levels
on the lower decks.
That should give us
enough power.
All right, I'll need
another 20 minutes
to get the projectors
on line.
All right.
The remote projectors are
charged and ready to go.
Imaging interface... stable.
Are you ready to try this?
I assume there's still
an emergency medical kit
behind the Tactical console?
That's right.
Then I'm ready.
There are a couple of things
you should know.
In order to do this,
I had to recalibrate
your containment field,
so your holo-matrix will be
very sensitive to disruption.
Try to stay away
from energy discharges--
phaser fire, force fields,
that sort of thing.
I'll try.
Make sure you do,
because if your containment
field collapses,
it'll take hours
to reinitialize your program.
Understood.
I'm going to head down
to Engineering
and try to get some of
the critical systems working.
You'll hear from me when I get
the com system back on line.
Unless, of course,
this doesn't work,
in which case, I'll see you
in about five seconds.
Good luck, Doctor.
Thank you.
I have a feeling I'll need it.
( electrical crackling )
( alarm beeping )
Well... it's bigger
than I thought.
( electrical crackling )
Captain?
( sighs in frustration )
( moans )
( groaning )
Hello, Captain.
You're going to be fine.
Oh, Doctor.
I see the new holo-projectors
are working.
Lieutenant Torres was able
to get them on line.
Are you feeling any pain,
dizziness, nausea?
I'm a little disoriented
and I have
one hell of a headache.
For some reason, none of
the tricorders are working,
but from what I can tell,
you have a concussion.
I'd like to get you to Sick Bay
as soon as possible.
The last thing I remember is
launching the escape pods.
Lieutenant Torres and I
were trying to stop
the core breach,
and then I blacked out.
You were successful in
preventing the breach.
And the crew?
They were taken prisoner
by the Kazon.
Torres to Bridge.
Can you hear me?
Yes, Lieutenant, we hear you.
Go ahead.
Are you all right, Captain?
Fine. I'm glad you
convinced the Doctor
to make a house call.
What's our status?
I've got communications
back on line,
and I think I can reactivate
the warp core, but it'll mean
recrystallizing
the entire dilithium matrix.
Keep on it.
In the meantime,
I'll see if I can restore
the Bridge controls
and start scanning
for the Kazon ships.
Aye, Captain.
Torres out.
Doctor, do you know anything
about bypassing a power relay?
Is it anything like
a coronary bypass?
Actually, it is.
Give me a hand.
See this conduit? It's a power
relay.
Its circuits are burnt out.
What we need to do
is reconfigure...
Neelix to Bridge.
Is anyone there? Emergency.
Neelix, this
is the Captain.
What's wrong?
Help, I need help!
I'm in the Mess Hall.
There's a--
( weapon blast )
Neelix, are you there?
Neelix!
With the turbolifts down,
it'll take me a half
hour to get there.
Doctor...
it's up to you.
I'll use the
remote projectors
to send you
to the Mess Hall.
Stand by for transfer.
( Neelix grunting )
I hope that crushed
your skull,
Kazon pus hog!
Kazon?
NEELIX:
What's it like to stare
death in the face, Kazon?
( clattering )
( grunting, mumbling )
Missed me.
( Kazon growling )
( weapon firing )
( grunting )
NEELIX:
I suggest you surrender now,
Kazon!
The Captain's
on her way.
( weapon fires )
( Neelix grunts )
( grunting )
NEELIX:
Gut spore!
You needle snake!
( growling )
( groaning )
( groans )
( sighs )
My best sauté pan.
Good work, Doctor.
You're injured.
( yells )
What's wrong?
Is it serious?
Don't panic, Mr. Neelix.
It looks superficial.
Am I going to die?
Not unless you're
allergic to tomatoes.
That isn't blood.
It's some kind of sauce.
Nondoran tomato paste.
Ooh! That'll leave
a nasty stain.
What are you
doing here, Doctor?
I could ask you
the same thing.
Kes and I were on our
way to the escape pod
when this Kazon fungus
came crawling
out an access hatch.
I kept him occupied long
enough for Kes to get away,
but he didn't
give up so easily.
So I took off running,
he chased me,
and I led him here.
No one gets the best
of me in my kitchen!
I'm fine now.
The question is, are you?
Me?
You're bleeding.
Bleeding?
That's impossible.
Don't panic, Doctor.
It looks superficial.
I'm not programmed to bleed.
Maybe you should
check your program.
Emergency Medical Hologram
to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Doctor.
Captain, we've captured a Kazon.
He's been rendered unconscious
and Mr. Neelix is fine.
But I believe my program
is malfunctioning.
I request that you return me
to Sick Bay immediately.
Acknowledged.
Mr. Neelix,
keep an eye on the Kazon
until I get there.
I'm on my way.
No problem, Captain.
( sighs )
Pain?
I'm not programmed to feel pain.
Heart rate?
Blood pressure?
Brain patterns?
( sighs )
Computer, analyze emergency
medical holographic program.
Has it been altered in any way
to include... life signs?
Unable to comply.
Requested program
is not on file.
Not on file?
The program's running right now.
Display schematics for all
Sick Bay holographic systems.
No holographic systems
exist in Sick Bay.
( sighs )
EMH Program AK-1
Diagnostic and Surgical
Subroutine Omega 323.
Check the database
and you'll find it.
Specified program
does not exist.
Well, then, who is
the Chief Medical Officer
on board this ship?
The Chief Medical Officer
of USS Voyager
is Dr. Lewis Zimmerman.
Lewis Zimmerman?
Yes. He was the engineer
who created my program.
I understand he resembles me,
but he's not on Voyager.
He's at the Jupiter Station
Holo-programming Center.
Computer, how long
has Doctor Zimmerman
served on Voyager?
Dr. Zimmerman commenced duty
on stardate 48308.2.
48308...
That's the date I was activated.
Computer, display all Starfleet
records on Dr. Lewis Zimmerman.
He looks a lot like me.
In fact,
he looks exactly like me.
Computer, is this me?
Affirmative.
Dr. Lewis Zimmerman.
( door opens )
Doctor, we've almost got
the warp core back on line,
but we need to know
where the crew was taken.
I want you
to perform an ARA scan
on the Kazon
while we question him.
Is something wrong?
Something's very wrong.
These tricorders
aren't picking up
any of your life signs.
At first, I thought
they were malfunctioning,
but now I find they show me
to be a living, breathing,
bleeding human being.
What?
And that's not all.
According to the computer,
I'm not a hologram.
I'm a real person
named "Zimmerman."
I've been trying
to analyze my program,
but the computer
says it doesn't exist.
This could be a problem
with the remote projectors.
The multiple
holographic signals
may be confusing
the computer.
I'm going to deactivate you
and then reinitialize
your program parameters.
Computer, discontinue emergency
medical holographic system.
See what I mean?
You're right.
Your program's
not anywhere on file.
Computer, shut down
all holographic systems
throughout the ship.
Computer, what happened
to Captain Janeway,
Lieutenant Torres, Mr. Neelix
and the Kazon?
All holographic simulations
were discontinued.
Simulations?
Computer, I'm talking
about real people.
Locate Captain Janeway.
Captain Janeway is stored
in memory block 47-alpha.
List all other programs
stored in that memory block.
This is
the entire Voyager crew.
Computer, are you saying
that the crew is nothing more
than a collection
of holographic programs?
Affirmative.
This is ridiculous.
There must be something wrong.
Doctor, am I glad
to see you.
Can you see me?
Of course I can see you.
Who are you?
Sir, it-it's me.
It's Lieutenant Barclay.
Reg... your assistant.
My assistant's name is Kes. Who
are you?
Uh-oh.
What?
Oh, no.
This is bad.
This is...
this is very bad.
Don't panic.
Uh... let's just try
to think our way through this.
I'm not familiar with you.
Are you a member of
the Voyager crew,
or have we encountered
another Federation ship?
Oh, boy!
The Voyager.
This is going to sound
a little crazy
from your perspective,
but you've got to trust me.
None of this is happening.
This is all
a holographic simulation
that you've been running.
What are you
talking about?
You're in the holodeck
at the Jupiter Station.
Your name
is Dr. Lewis Zimmerman.
You're a holo-engineer
and you've been running
a program that's malfunctioning
and we've been trying
to reach you.
What are you saying?
That I'm a... real person?
Well, I always used
to think of you that way
and I-I know your wife
tends to think...
My wife?
We'd, uh...
we'd better take this
one step at a time.
Please do.
Well, uh, you see,
this, uh, starship,
it's not really
a starship.
It was a program
that you wrote
to study
the psychological impact
of long-term isolation
on a crew
made up of Starfleet
and Maquis crew members.
A program I wrote?
That's preposterous.
I'm the program.
Voyager is a real ship,
manned by real people.
I'm afraid not.
This must have something to do
with the radiation surge.
What was that?
Well, we've been
having problems
shutting the program down
because of a kinoplasmic
radiation surge on the station.
It's affected all
of the computer systems,
including the holodecks.
The radiation must be affecting
the memory centers
of your brain.
How did you get in here?
Oh, I'm not really here.
Clearly, I'm here
because we're talking.
You see, what I mean is,
I'm in a control booth
outside of the holodeck.
What you see
is a projection of my body,
so that we can communicate.
We've been trying to get in here
or send a com signal in
for nearly six hours.
You expect me to believe
that the past six months
I've spent on this ship
have been nothing
but a simulation?
You haven't been here
six months.
You've only been here six hours.
That's impossible.
I have very clear memories of
my first appearance on Voyager,
meeting Captain Janeway
for the first time.
I've had numerous experiences
aboard this ship.
That's all part
of the simulation.
How do I know you're
not some type of alien
impersonating
a Starfleet officer?
Look, Doctor,
it's very important
that you believe me.
You're losing your
sense of identity.
You're starting to think
that you're part
of the program
and that's...
that's not good.
It's called HTDS--
holo-transference
dementia syndrome.
So now I'm having
a psychotic episode.
No. Yes! I mean,
maybe the radiation...
Doctor, I'm sorry
I have to do this.
How dare you?
It hurt, right?
If you were a program,
it wouldn't hurt.
I-I could be programmed
to think it hurt.
Doctor!
I'll be back.
I've got to discuss this
with the others.
Don't... don't go anywhere.
Pain.
Why would I have pain?
I think I'm hungry.
I'm not sure what for,
but I'm definitely hungry.
This is impossible.
The problem is worse
than we thought.
The, uh, radiation is
disrupting the command protocol,
so we can't shut
the program down
and while the program
is running,
we can't access
the holodeck grid.
Why don't you
beam me out of here?
We tried, but the radiation
is interfering
with the transporters
and we can't get a lock on you.
I've consulted with our
neurologist, Dr. Kaplan,
and he said that if we
can't get you out of here
within the next hour,
that the radiation
would completely oxidize
your neuro-cellular structures.
So, what do you suggest?
There's only one way left
to terminate the program
and that's to play it out.
Bring it to its conclusion,
and once the simulation ends,
it'll release the access locks
on the holodeck arch,
and we can get you out of here.
How does it conclude?
You programmed
two possible outcomes.
Either Voyager finds its way
back to Federation space
or it's destroyed
in the process.
But the simulation
was designed to run for weeks
before either happens.
But I know of a way
that you can bring it
to an end right now.
Destroy the ship.
Destroy the ship?
Destroy Voyager?
This is just a
simulation, Lewis.
None of this is real
and unless you
destroy this ship
that you think you're on,
you're going to die.
No. No, absolutely not.
Doctor, it's the only way.
First of all,
I don't even know
how to destroy the ship.
Second of all, I wouldn't
do it even if I could.
And third, how do I know
you're not an alien intruder
trying to trick me
into killing everyone?
Well... those are
good questions.
First, I can tell you
how to destroy the Voyager.
Second, if you don't do it,
you're going to die.
And third... well,
I'm just not an alien
and I don't know how else
to convince you of that.
If what you're saying is true,
why don't you destroy the ship?
Why do I have to do it?
You're the one running
the simulation.
It's coded to respond
to your input,
not mine.
I'm sorry, Mr. Barclay--
if that's what your
name really is--
but you're not
very convincing.
Here. Use this tricorder.
Scan the room out
to a distance of 15 meters.
This appears to show
a wall 15 meters away
and it does have a holodeck
grid configuration.
You see?
But you could be manipulating
these readings.
Scan me!
You'll see I'm
a holographic projection
originating
from beyond that wall.
Yes. All right.
But it could still be
an elaborate deception.
I can't take that risk.
There has to be some way
to convince you.
Oh, I know.
I'll be right back.
( concerned voices )
MALE: Orderly! Here.
( alarm beeping )
Are you the Emergency
Medical Hologram?
Yes, of course I am.
Well, we've got wounded here.
I've seen this patient before.
He has multiple
percussive injuries.
Tricorder.
Medical tricorder.
I've been in this moment
in time before.
What? What are you talking
about? Help this man.
Have we just been catapulted
across the galaxy
to an unknown area
of the Delta Quadrant?
Yes.
And you are developing
tumorous growths on your chest.
What?
Ah, so...
that hasn't happened yet.
Is this stardate 48308?
Look, are you going
to help this man or not?
I'm not. Mr. Barclay.
The program must
be malfunctioning.
Let me see if I can reset
the holographic projector.
Mr. Barclay, will
you please return?
Now do you believe me?
This is the beginning
of the simulation.
We can't shut down
the program,
but we can restart it.
This is my
first memory
of being activated on Voyager.
Who the hell
are you?!
Did I program Mr. Paris
to be so annoying?
Actually, I programmed him.
I modeled him
after my cousin Frank.
Hmm...
Computer, delete Paris.
What are you...?
What did you do to him?
Computer, delete Kim.
Hmm.
Are you convinced yet?
Let's just say that your
credibility level is rising,
but I'm still not prepared
to destroy Voyager.
So what are you
going to do now?
I need to confirm
my true nature,
whether or not I am
in fact a real person.
Let's just say
that I'm right
and this is a real ship,
and I'm a hologram.
If I were to destroy the
holographic memory core,
then I should disappear.
Yes, but if you destroy it
and you're still here...
Then I'm not a hologram.
And you'll know
that I'm telling you the truth.
The holo-memory core is
located in Engineering.
Let's go.
( alarm sounding )
What's wrong?
The remote holo-projectors
were taken off line.
I shouldn't be able
to exist outside Sick Bay.
That's because you're a...
A real person. Yes.
I'm getting the idea.
Magnetic constrictors
are on line.
The warp core is stable.
Let's get started
on those plasma relays.
You. Who are you?
I'm the Emergency
Medical Hologram.
I didn't know you could be
projected into Engineering.
I can't,
but it's a long story.
I'd rather not get
into it right now.
Fine. We have three wounded
crew members over here.
I'm afraid I have
a more pressing matter
to attend to, Captain.
What do you mean,
you have a more pressing
matter to attend to?
And who are you? I don't
recognize you.
Oh, don't mind me. I'm just
assisting the Doctor.
Doctor, I am ordering you
to take care
of these wounded crew members.
Computer, delete Janeway.
The program's not responding
to vocal commands.
The protocols are
starting to freeze up.
We don't have much time.
Jarvis, Parsons,
put these men under arrest.
Don't worry.
Those phasers aren't real.
They're just holograms.
I wouldn't be so sure.
I was injured earlier.
That means
the holodeck safeties are off.
Now just a moment.
Let's not do
anything hasty.
Who are you?
Are you two responsible
for bringing us here?
Actually, no.
The Array you discovered
is controlled by an entity
you will come to know
as the Caretaker
or banjo-man.
He's actually an alien life-form
who is caring for a species
known as the Ocampa,
who live nearby.
Enough.
I don't know what
this is all about,
but clearly, you're involved.
Take them to the brig.
I'll question them later.
DOCTOR: Mm, no,
I don't think so.
You're in no position to argue.
I'm not arguing. I'm simply
pointing out
that in several seconds, the
entire crew of Voyager
will be transported
to the Array,
where you will be tortured
and probed for
medical information.
It will be quite painful,
but not fatal.
Bridge to Janeway.
We're being scanned
by the Array, Captain.
It's penetrated our shields.
What kind of scan?
Bridge?
Janeway to Bridge.
Respond.
What are you--?
Time is running out, Doctor.
The oxidation levels
in your neural tissues
are rising.
You've got
to destroy this ship
and bring this program
to an end.
First things first.
I have to make absolutely
sure what I am.
This is the central
memory nexus
for all holographic
systems on board.
If I destroy this,
there won't be a single
hologram left on Voyager.
Well, except for me.
I'm being projected from
outside the simulation.
Go ahead.
Give it a try.
Convinced?
DOCTOR:
Computer, what is the status
of the holographic
imaging system on Voyager?
The holographic imaging system
has been destroyed.
Are there any
holographic programs
running anywhere on the ship?
Negative.
Then why is the ship still
here and not a holo-grid?
Please restate the question.
You said all holo-systems
were destroyed.
Why is the ship simulation
still running?!
All holo-simulations
have been terminated.
Doctor, I-I know this
is a little confusing,
but try to remember
that you just destroyed
the holographic imaging system
on a holographic ship--
A hologram
in a hologram.
If you want
to bring this to an end,
you've got to destroy
the entire simulation,
the ship itself.
Then it's true.
I am... a real person.
And you're a person
in great danger.
Destroy the ship
now, before it's too late.
( sighs )
But if I'm wrong...
Doctor, you've got
to believe me.
What else can I do
to prove it to you?
I know, I know,
but it's just so...
( groans )
There.
You see what's
happening?
Holograms don't
feel pain.
Your brain is being flooded
with kinoplasmic radiation.
You're dying.
I... I guess you're right.
Oh...!
What should I do?
The warp core.
Even set on full power,
it's going to take
a sustained phaser burst
to punch through
the outer duranium shielding.
Set your phaser
to maximum.
Aim for the magnetic
constrictors.
Ready?
Ready.
CHAKOTAY:
Stop!
Doctor,
don't listen to him.
He's lying.
Step away from the warp core,
Doctor.
Don't do anything
that man tells you.
You're in danger if you do. None
of this is real.
So I've been told.
It's all
a holographic simulation.
That's right, but it's not
the simulation you think it is.
Everything around you is part
of a holographic projection
that's being created
by your program.
My program?
You're on the holodeck
on Voyager.
The Captain suggested
you take a day off,
try a holo-novel,
so you did.
But while you were running
the holo-novel,
there was a kinoplasmic
radiation surge
in the imaging system.
It created a feedback
loop between
the holodeck computer
and your program.
All of this,
including Mr. Barclay,
is a holographic simulation
generated by your codes,
subroutines
and memory
circuits.
Don't be distracted by these
holographic characters.
Stay focused on
what you need to do,
destroy the warp core.
Wait a minute.
The entire crew of Voyager
was just taken by the Array.
They won't be back
for three days.
So what's he doing here?
The program is
malfunctioning.
Are you the real
Commander Chakotay
or a holographic projection
like Mr. Barclay?
I'm a projection.
I'm really at the holographic
control station in Engineering.
You're trapped on the holodeck.
We've been monitoring
the program from here
and we've been trying
to reach you for hours.
Sounds familiar.
He told me the same thing.
Doctor, do you remember
coming into the holodeck
and running a holo-novel
within the last six hours?
No.
No, I don't.
That's because your memory
circuits
are being eradicated
by the feedback loop.
We have to get you
off the holodeck.
Transfer you back
to Sick Bay.
You don't have
memory circuits.
You have a mind, and
it's being damaged.
Destroy the Voyager,
the program will end
and we can get you
off the holodeck.
That's not true, Doctor.
Because of the feedback loop,
if you destroy the simulation,
you will be destroyed as well.
Me?
If you shut down
this simulation,
your program will be wiped out
right along with it.
There'll be no way
to retrieve the lost data.
You'll be gone.
Oh...
( moans )
Only real people
experience pain.
You've got to believe me.
What you're perceiving as pain
is really the feedback loop
eradicating your
memory circuits.
What...
what is it you
want me to do?
Don't do anything.
We're working on the
problem right now.
We're close to a solution.
Do nothing
and you'll die.
( groans )
Doctor... trust me.
KES:
Trust me, Lewis.
Kes?
Yes, you know me.
You remember me.
Yes.
You're my assistant.
BARCLAY:
I told you.
His brain is being damaged.
He's losing his memory.
This is Kes Zimmerman,
your wife.
CHAKOTAY:
This is all
a holographic delusion
drawn from people
and experiences
in your own memory circuits. You
are malfunctioning.
Lewis, please, listen to Reg.
He's trying to help you.
Destroy this program.
If you listen to her, you'll
end up destroying yourself.
KES:
Believe in yourself.
You're not a program.
You're a real,
flesh-and-blood human being...
and you're my husband.
I don't want to lose you.
Lewis...
how would you rather
think of yourself,
as a real person
with a real life,
with a family that loves you,
or as some hologram
that exists in a Sick Bay
on a starship
lost in deep space?
This isn't about what you want.
This is about what you are.
Just because you're made
of projected light and energy
doesn't mean
you're any less real
than someone made
of flesh and blood.
It doesn't matter
what you're made of.
What matters is who you are.
You're our friend.
And we want you back.
Lewis, please.
Pick up the phaser.
Destroy the warp core.
It's your only hope.
Doctor...
we're close
to getting you out of here.
Try to hold on.
Whatever happens,
I just want you
to know I love you.
I...
I always wanted
to tell you, Kes...
that you're beautiful.
Thank you.
What's going on?
We were able to shut down
the holodeck simulation
that your program
was generating.
Commander Chakotay
transferred you
back to Sick Bay.
You seem to have
suffered no damage.
What really happened?
Voyager encountered
a subspace anomaly,
which created
a kinoplasmic radiation surge
throughout
most of our computers.
Unfortunately,
it happened
while you were
using the holodeck.
We've been working
for the past six hours
to get you out of there.
So there was never
a Kazon attack.
KES:
That's right.
And the crew didn't really
abandon ship.
No. In fact, except
for the computer problems,
it has been an uneventful day.
And who is this Lieutenant
Barclay I imagined?
Barclay was part
of the original engineering team
that designed your program.
He was in charge of testing
your interpersonal skills.
Oh.
This should make
an interesting paper.
Chakotay to Sick Bay.
Is the Doctor all right?
Yes, Commander.
His program is
functioning normally.
Good work. As soon as you're
finished there,
I want all senior officers
to report to the Bridge.
Acknowledged.
It's good to have you back,
Doctor.
Well... I suppose
I should begin cataloguing
the niotrinate samples
I was working on this morning.
So you really think
I'm beautiful.
I was under a great deal
of stress, you understand.
I may have said things
that are not necessarily
my true feelings.
Oh.
Then you don't think
I'm beautiful.
I didn't say that, exactly.
I... I consider you very...
very attractive...
in a platonic sense.
I see.
Then you don't really love me?
I'm afraid not.
( sighs )
Then I guess
our marriage is over.
Our marriage?
Are you making a joke?
It isn't a joke
to me, Lewis.
I know we
have problems,
but I think we
can solve them.
No.
No... this-this can't be right.
Something's wrong here.
It's not too late, Lewis.
You can still save yourself
by destroying the warp core.
No...
( groans )
No, I don't believe you.
None of this is real.
It's all a delusion.
Somebody help me!
I am helping you.
Listen to him, Lewis.
No!
Doctor, are you
listening to me?!
That man needs help!
JANEWAY'S VOICE:
Try to calm down, Doctor.
Everything's going to be fine.
Doctor?
Do you know who I am?
Do you know
where you are?
I appear to be on
the holodeck grid.
That's right.
And do you know
what you are?
Yes. I'm...
I'm the emergency
medical holographic program.
Right?
Right.
Well, I assume
everything that's happened
took place here
on the holodeck?
CHAKOTAY:
That's right. We encountered
a subspace anomaly
and there was a radiation
surge in the computer system.
And Kes is my assistant...
not my wife?
Your wife?
Never mind.
Captain, if it's okay,
I'd like to return
to Sick Bay now.
Of course.
It's good to have you back,
Doctor.
It's good to be back.
Computer, transfer
EMH program to Sick Bay.
We were married?
It was a delusion, of course.
I understand...
but I'd still prefer it
if you didn't tell
Neelix about this.
He tends to get
a little jealous.
It'll be our secret.
I am curious about one thing.
What's that?
The radiation surge
caused my program to malfunction
and my codes and circuits
began to degrade,
and yet, instead of detecting
that threat to my program,
I experienced
an elaborate delusion
concerning the nature
of my existence,
human or hologram.
Person... or projection.
Why?
Why would my program focus
on such an esoteric dilemma?
Well...
I sometimes ask
those kind of questions.
Who am I?
What am I doing here?
What's my purpose in life?
Doesn't everybody?
Not me.
I know exactly who I am
and what my purpose is.
I am
the Emergency Medical Hologram
aboard the Starship Voyager.
Are you sure about that?
( door opens and closes )
Hmm.