Oh, sir...
we, um... we're just...
Yes, I can see that.
What was that all about?
I'd call it an example
of indiscreet shipboard
fraternization.
Really? Sorry I missed it.
Deck 6.
( chuckling )
Thank you for
your help, Tom.
Yeah. See you later.
Right.
Here's the cabbage
you asked for.
Is something wrong?
What's this?
A spawn beetle.
Oh, they cross-pollinate
the Oblissian cabbage.
Have you ever seen
such fascinating striations?
Oh, isn't it
beautiful?
I doubt the Captain
would think so
if she found it crawling around
in her salad.
( growls )
There is something wrong.
What is it?
No, nothing. I'm just very busy.
( clears throat )
So you're seeing
Tom Paris later.
What?
No, not that I know of.
He said, "See you later."
You said, "Right."
Is he helping you
in the airponics bay now?
He was just helping
me carry these.
How thoughtful.
Neelix, this is getting
ridiculous.
You're imagining things
that aren't there.
You're such an innocent!
I see the way he looks at you.
I used to look at women
that way. I know what it means.
Janeway to the senior staff.
Please report to the Bridge.
Take care.
Thank you for bringing
the cabbage.
I can handle this
from here, thank you.
We've detected a strange
energy configuration
off the port bow.
Any idea what it is?
It appears to be some sort
of magnetic disturbance.
We're going to take
a closer look.
You seem a little
preoccupied, Commander.
This morning,
I interrupted a couple
who were kissing
in the turbolift.
And I've been wondering
if we should establish
a policy regarding...
fraternization.
Well...
the couple in question
might be urged
to show a bit more discretion,
but Starfleet has always
been reluctant
to regulate
people's personal lives.
Of course, but we're in
a unique situation here.
The development
of intimate relationships
might cause us problems that
wouldn't arise in other ships.
I understand
what you're saying, but...
we're a long way from home.
Everyone is lonely,
and all we have is each other.
I think, eventually,
people will begin to pair off.
Including you?
As Captain, that's a luxury
I don't have.
Besides, I intend for us
to be home before...
before Mark
gives me up for dead.
We're in visual range,
Captain.
On screen.
CHAKOTAY:
Looks like some type
of energetic vapor.
Magnify.
Space-dwelling life-forms.
Full sensor
scan, Mr. Kim.
Their internal energy patterns
appear to be consistent
with discrete
organic processes.
Captain, I'd like the chance
to study them at close range.
So would I, Commander.
But let's not get too close.
We wouldn't want to disturb
their natural behavior.
Half impulse, Mr. Paris.
Take us into bio-scanner range.
Aye, Captain.
The swarm is not
particularly dense, Captain.
I estimate their number
at fewer than 2,000.
They're really moving.
KIM: He's right.
They've accelerated
to a velocity
of approximately
1,000 kilometers per second.
It's possible we're
frightening them.
Keep us within
scanner range, Lieutenant,
but try to avoid
rapid acceleration.
Aye, Captain.
Take a look at this.
See the way they
propel themselves?
JANEWAY:
They seem
to flagellate,
almost like protozoa.
Exactly,
but they're achieving
incredible speeds--
over 3,000 kilometers
per second.
Ensign Wildman, scan the field
for repeating patterns.
Maybe they're capable of
some type of communication.
Aye, Captain.
CHAKOTAY:
Their internal anatomy's
also very unusual.
They don't appear to have a
digestive system of any kind,
but they have an extremely
porous outer covering.
My guess would be that they
absorb nutrients
directly from space.
Incredible.
A space-dwelling life-form
capable of metabolizing
inorganic matter.
WILDMAN:
Particle density
in this part of space
isn't very high.
That might explain why they
have to keep moving so fast.
Feeding at 3,000
kilometers per second.
Not exactly leisurely
dining, is it?
( door chimes )
Come in.
For you, sweeting.
Thank you.
Hmm... what's the occasion?
Oh, no occasion.
I... I just wanted
to apologize.
Apologize?
For the way I acted
in the Mess Hall.
I-I was jealous.
I know.
I just wish you could trust me.
It has nothing to do
with trusting you.
It's him I don't trust.
I've seen
his kind before.
They're all over the Quadrant,
as a matter of fact.
They prey on naive, sheltered
young women like you.
What are you looking for?
A vase.
Don't!
What's this?
Nothing. Just a snack.
A Terran delicacy.
Ensign Wildman
told me about it.
Mashed potatoes with butter.
It's delicious.
Would you like to try it?
Ugh. Awful.
How can you eat it?
I can't stop eating it.
I've had six bowls.
And the reason it
tastes so strange--
I put a container
of nitrogenated soil in it.
Dirt?
You're eating dirt?
Why?
I don't know,
but this morning...
What?
You remember the spawn beetles?
You... you didn't...?
Neelix to Sick Bay.
Prepare to receive
an emergency patient.
I'm not sick.
I feel fine.
I just can't... stop eating.
We are going to get
to the bottom of this.
Come on.
No! I'm not going!
We are going to Sick Bay.
No!
I'll call Security unless
you come with me. Holy...
Come on.
( muffled ): Stop it!
Put me down!
They're changing course
again, Captain,
and accelerating.
Should I follow them?
I'm concerned that
we're disturbing them.
Let's drop back a bit, give them
a little more room.
Yes, ma'am.
KIM:
Captain, we're accelerating.
We're getting closer
to the swarm.
Mr. Paris?
I'm trying to
slow down, Captain.
KIM:
Our velocity doesn't correspond
to impulse reactor output.
We're moving much faster
than we ought to be.
They seem to be... pulling us
toward them.
TUVOK:
Sensors indicate
an EM resonance field.
The creatures
seem to be creating
their own magnetic wake. That is
what is pulling the ship.
We're getting closer.
Mr. Paris, reverse thrusters.
Helm controls aren't
responding, Captain.
Mr. Tuvok, raise shields.
( console beeping )
Nonfunctional, Captain.
They're pulling us in.
Damage report.
Life support's functioning
normally, Captain,
but there's a huge fluctuation
in the EPS grids.
It's wreaking havoc
with the impulse engines.
Warp drive's still on line.
One burst, and we'd
be out of here.
But our exhaust could
seriously harm the creatures.
Janeway to Torres.
Do you have any thoughts about
how to get us out of this swarm
without engaging warp engines?
We might try something like
a targ scoop.
Can you enlighten us,
Lieutenant?
Klingons put them on the front
of ground assault vehicles.
They emit
a high-frequency tone
that disperses targ herds
in their path.
I can modify the main deflector
to create
an inverted magnetic pulse.
Project it toward the swarm.
It might be enough to... nudge
the creatures out of the way.
Good idea, Lieutenant.
Proceed.
You're sure the beetles
weren't poisonous?
Or the flowers?
There are no toxins
present in her system.
Doctor, why is she eating
all these strange things?
What's wrong with her?
I am conducting
an examination
in order to
determine that.
But don't you have any ideas?
Her unusual appetite
may merely indicate
a nutrient deficiency.
It is not unusual
for humanoids
to crave foods that are rich
in the very vitamins
and minerals that their
bodies are lacking.
You... you can't mean
my body lacks dirt.
Her body temperature is
elevated 3.9 degrees.
She's burning up.
And I'm detecting
elevated levels
of electrophoretic activity
in her nervous system.
You have
to bring them down.
There is increased
electrophoretic activity
in the ship's atmosphere,
probably created by
the creatures we're studying.
You mean,
there's a connection
between what's happening to Kes
and those creatures?
You have to do
something about it!
You are making it impossible
for me to think,
much less treat my patient.
You must leave.
I won't.
Kes needs me.
Leave now
or I will call Security.
You can't talk
to me that way.
This is my Sick Bay
and I will decide
what goes on here.
But...
Get out!
I'll be back.
Don't worry
about a thing.
( sighs )
Captain, may I
speak with you?
It's a matter
of some urgency.
What is it, Neelix?
I have been thrown
out of Sick Bay.
And I'm just wondering
if you feel it's appropriate
for a hologram to banish
a flesh and blood person,
who should have the right
to be at the bedside
of his loved one,
who is extremely ill.
Kes is extremely ill?
The hologram
doesn't have a clue
as to what's wrong
with her.
Though it may have something
to do with these creatures.
But he still won't
let me offer comfort
to the woman I love
at a time when my place
is clearly by her side.
Just how is Kes being
affected by the swarm?
That's what I
wanted to know,
but before I
got any answers,
I was summarily
dismissed.
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Janeway here.
Captain, I think you'd
better come down here.
There's a bit of a problem.
I'm on my way.
Commander, you have the Bridge.
Notify me immediately
of any change in our status.
Aye, Captain.
( Kes panting )
I was conducting tests.
She was none too cooperative,
let me assure you.
Then suddenly,
she screeched
and shoved me out of the
way, went into my office
and proceeded to erect a-a
force field at the door.
I can't lower it.
She's keeping me
out of my own office.
NEELIX:
Sweeting.
( gasping )
What's wrong?
Please come out.
I was able to complete
several tests
before she
became delirious.
Her fever has increased and her
pulse
and blood pressure are
dangerously high.
Do you have any idea
what's causing these symptoms?
I suspect it's the
electrophoretic levels
being created by the swarm.
We should leave
immediately.
Unfortunately, that's
not an option at the moment,
but we're working on it.
There's one more thing.
I discovered a strange
growth on her back.
It's unlike any other
tumorous substance
I've ever seen
or studied before.
And it was not there the
last time I examined her.
( panting )
I'll try to talk to her.
Kes, please come out.
You can eat
anything you want.
Captain.
Why don't you let me try?
Kes, please listen to me.
We think you're being affected
by a swarm
of space-dwelling life-forms.
We're doing everything we can
to get away from them.
And when we do, you'll probably
start feeling better.
Are you... saying that's
not what's wrong with you?
( sighs deeply )
Kes... please, let me come in.
Tell me
what it is.
Maybe I can help.
Shh.
It's going to be all right.
Now...
tell me what is
happening to you.
Di-did the Doctor
tell you
he found something
growing on my back?
Yes, a growth
of some kind.
It's the mitral sac.
It's where my child
would grow.
I'm going through
the elogium--
the time of change--
when my body prepares
for fertilization.
Humans go through
the same kind of process.
It's called puberty.
But I'm too young.
Much too young.
It usually happens
between the ages
of four and five.
I'm-I'm not even two yet.
Listen to me.
All your body's metabolic
activity has increased.
It's possible
your reproductive processes
are being accelerated
as a result.
I'm not ready.
We're going to get you
through this, Kes.
The Doctor will monitor
you constantly.
You don't understand.
The elogium occurs only once.
If I am ever going
to have a child,
it has to be now!
No change, Captain.
We're still being pulled
along with the swarm.
PARIS:
Heading 121, mark 7.
Speed now 6,000
kilometers per second.
All systems are functioning
within normal parameters.
How is Torres coming
with the modifications
to the main deflector?
Her last report estimated
they'd be finished
in another half hour.
Let me know
as soon as she's ready.
Join me, Commander?
Kes is terribly
frightened.
She's had no time
to prepare for this,
and the decision has
to be made in the next
40 or 50 hours.
She's going to discuss
it with Neelix, but...
there are
so many unknowns.
There might be risks
in procreating this early.
And of course
there's no guarantee
they're genetically
compatible,
or that Neelix
has any interest
in becoming a father.
Seems your concerns
about fraternization
were... prophetic.
I wasn't even thinking
about procreation,
but I suppose it's...
the inevitable outcome.
We should consider the fact
that it might be necessary
for the crew to start
having children.
It might take us
a long time to get home.
If it does take 75 years,
we're going to need
a replacement crew
in about half that time.
( sighs )
Who'd have thought
we'd be considering
a generational ship
when we were ordered
on a three-week mission.
I know,
but it's a problem
we have to face now.
What would that mean
for the children?
What kind of life
would we be giving them?
Aboard a starship,
traveling through a potentially
hostile part of space.
And are we equipped to provide
for their needs--
child-care,
educational facilities.
We'd be building
an entire community
on board this ship.
That's a massive commitment.
Are you prepared to tell them
they can't have children?
I can't do that.
And I've made it clear
to Kes that it's her choice
whether to have a child
or not, but...
Mmm.
There aren't any
easy answers here...
for any of us.
Are you saying that,
unless you conceive now,
you'll never be able to?
Yes, and I need you
to help me decide,
because I would want
you to mate with me.
( gasps )
I'm... I'm... I'm...
honored.
But are you entirely
certain it would be safe?
Safe?
You're so young.
Is it dangerous for you
to conceive a child
at your age?
I don't know. I've never known
anyone
as young as I am
who had a baby.
If you never had a child,
would you...
be terribly unhappy?
Yes!
I-I mean...
I think so.
I don't know.
I always assumed
I'd be a mother someday--
just not so soon.
What about you?
Didn't you think
you'd be a father someday?
Well, to be honest, uh...
I've never given it
much thought.
Until now, my life
has been so... itinerant.
There's no way
I could have provided
the stability
a child would need.
But now it's different,
isn't it?
Well...
yes.
But...
raising a child on a starship--
that's hardly what I would
call the ideal environment.
You don't want
a child, do you?
That's not it at all.
I'm just trying to look
at all sides
of the issue.
Bringing a child
into the world...
it's a huge responsibility.
I know you'd want
to be sure
we're both up to the task.
I-I mean, somebody would
have to keep their eye
on the little guy all the time,
or he'd be off sticking
his finger into an EM conduit
or playing
with the plasma injectors.
That's right. That's
called being a parent.
What about your medical studies?
You wouldn't be able
to continue them
if you had a child.
Of course I would!
You're just making excuses.
All you're thinking about
is yourself.
How much trouble a child
would be for you.
Look!
What's that?
The ipasaphor.
It makes the mating
bond possible.
It does?
If we begin,
we must stay bonded
for six days.
Six days?
In order to ensure conception.
And after the ipasaphor appears,
we only have 50 hours
to begin the process.
So I need to know your answer.
Uh, well, uh...
50 hours.
That's... good.
That's good.
We can sleep on it.
I'll get back to you.
( man coughing )
Sorry.
I swear I heard you say
lots of pepper sauce.
What is the lunch
special today?
Well, actually, I didn't
get around to making
a lunch special.
But we have some lovely
gabosti stew left over
from last night.
Very well, it will do.
I've... had
quite a run on it
as a matter of fact.
It seems very popular.
If it is all
you are serving,
that would stand to reason.
You can have it with or without
pepper sauce.
Without.
Oh...
Mr. Tuvok...
I was wondering.
You have children,
don't you?
I have four.
Four! My!
That's certainly
quite a family.
Tell me...
what's it like
being a father?
The question is so broad,
it is difficult to respond.
Well, I mean, it's a lot
of responsibility, isn't it?
Watching them.
Caring for them.
Keeping them safe.
Giving them an education.
That is
certainly true.
Sounds like it's
a lot more trouble
than it's worth.
Mr. Neelix,
I am aware of your situation.
It appears you are in some doubt
as to the wisdom
of becoming a parent.
It's just
all happening so fast!
I don't know what to think.
I can only tell you
that if you have considerable
doubts about fatherhood,
it would not be wise
to enter into the process.
It is so much more overwhelming
than one expects
that I believe only
the most committed
should become parents.
Ah...
That's what I thought.
However,
I must point out
that, as illogical as it seems,
being a father can have
infinite rewards--
far more than
would seem possible.
My children occupy a significant
portion of my thoughts,
now more than ever.
I have heard it said
that children can bring a lot
of joy into one's life.
I experience
neither joy nor sorrow,
but I do believe it is possible.
Now that I think about it,
it might be fun
to have a little guy around.
And we could do a lot together.
I've got quite a bit
I could teach a boy, you know--
survival methods,
piloting skills,
romantic techniques.
If you say so.
But I must point out
that there is an equal chance
that you would have a daughter.
A daughter?
I don't have anything
to teach a daughter.
Why would it be any different
from what you would teach a son?
It just would.
She'd learn more
from her mother.
I have three sons and one
daughter.
I can assure you,
she benefits
as much from my presence
and guidance
as my sons do.
It is unfortunate
that I must be so far removed
from all of them now.
I understand.
We'll get there, Mr. Vulcan.
I'm sure of it.
Thank you.
You've given me a lot
to think about.
We're ready to generate
the inverted
magnetic pulse, Captain.
Proceed.
Initiating the field.
( console beeping )
( beeping intensifies )
TORRES:
It's working.
Are the creatures all right,
Commander?
Yes, Captain,
they seem to be fine.
Let's try to keep it that way.
Thrusters at 200 kph, Mr. Paris.
Ease us out of here.
Aye, Captain.
What are they doing?
CHAKOTAY: Hard to know
what's prompting that behavior.
Maybe they think we're
making a hostile move.
Report.
I'm reading a massive energy
drain in all ship systems.
Impulse engines
are losing power.
Captain, some of the life-forms
have attached themselves
to the warp nacelles.
Guidance, navigational and
tactical systems are failing.
How soon will we clear
the swarm, Lieutenant?
In a few seconds.
We're almost out.
Captain, I am detecting
a substantial magnetic mass
moving rapidly
toward the port bow.
WILDMAN:
It's physiologically similar
to the smaller creatures,
just a lot bigger.
TUVOK:
Perhaps it is
the parent.
Or it could be
a difference in gender.
It's hard to say
without further observation.
With all due respect,
Captain,
haven't we done
enough observing?
These creatures have attacked
the ship's key systems.
For all we know, they were
setting us up for an attack.
It's possible.
Mr. Paris,
let's keep moving.
If we can put some distance
between us and the swarm,
maybe the ones on our nacelles
will drop off and
rejoin their friends.
Aye, Captain. 200 kph.
The larger creature
is moving with us.
( console beeping )
Now what?
The creature has emitted
an electrically charged
plasma stream.
All stop.
Damage report.
No significant damage, Captain.
Shields are holding.
A plasma blast
is a hostile move.
Shouldn't we be thinking
about responding?
If the creature threatens
serious damage to the ship,
I'll consider it an enemy.
Until then,
they're all to be treated
as indigenous life-forms
behaving normally
in their natural habitat. We're
the intruders here.
Captain, look at this.
They're attaching
themselves
to the large creature the
same way they did to us.
KIM:
And I think
I know why.
That plasma stream it ejected
has almost the same subspace
signature as our warp nacelles.
Then the smaller
creatures are attracted
to our subspace emissions.
Perhaps in the same way
some species are attracted
to pheromones.
Pheromones?
You think it's a
sexual attraction?
Color change
and provocative movement
are frequently associated
with mating rituals.
Then... these guys think
we're one of them?
Well, their behavior
toward us
and the large creature
is similar.
It's possible they've mistaken
us for a potential mate.
( door chimes )
Yes?
Well, order the diapers.
We're about to become parents.
You mean, you want to mate with
me?
More than anything.
But you were making excuses.
I didn't think you
wanted to be a father.
I just hadn't
thought it through.
Now that I have, I swear
to you I want to do this.
And I'll be the best
possible father to our child.
I know you will.
So...
what comes next?
Before we begin
the mating process,
I have to go through
a certain ritual
called the rolisisin.
What does that involve?
One of my parents has
to massage my feet
until my tongue
begins to swell.
Uh, where do you plan
to find a parent?
If Captain Janeway weren't
so busy I'd ask her,
but I'm sure
the Doctor would do it.
Will that work?
Since he's not a real person?
The Doctor is
very real to me.
I don't know how I feel
about him massaging your feet.
It's a ritual.
Someone has to do it.
Okay. Okay, fine.
How long will that take?
About an hour.
Then I'll be back.
Fascinating.
The stimulation
to the sympathetic nerves
must set off
a hormonal reaction,
which activates
glandular activity
in the tissues of the tongue.
I've never seen
this response before.
Although in a species
known as the Gree,
stimulating follicles
on the proboscis
results in a swelling
of the auricular canal.
Doctor?
Yes?
Am I doing the
right thing?
You'll have to tell me.
I know nothing of this ritual.
No, I mean, am I doing
the right thing
by conceiving a child?
If I were at home now, my father
would be performing
the rolisisin with me.
It's the time when
parent and child
move into a new kind
of relationship.
As the child
has her own child,
the parent must acknowledge
her true adulthood.
I see.
My father and I were very close.
He was such a wise man.
I miss him.
Sometimes, I think I hear
his voice in my head.
It's almost as
though he were here
helping to guide me.
I'm sorry.
I must be feeling lonely
for home.
It's probably a result
of the elogium...
( sighs )
but I really would appreciate
your advice.
Your help.
I need someone's guidance.
I can discuss
delivery methods...
or pediatric situations.
I'm afraid I don't have
much perspective to offer
about becoming a parent.
Neither do I.
As long as Neelix
was opposed to the idea,
trying to get out of it,
I was certain that I wanted
to have a child,
but when he said
that he wanted one too,
suddenly, I was very frightened.
Perhaps a statistical survey
will offer a context.
Among the Breen,
pregnancy at a young age
is a common event.
The Breen, of course,
is one of the most warlike
of species.
And then there
are the Scathos.
Any woman who
conceives a child
before her fourth decade
is summarily executed.
Maybe I just felt
I should have a child
because I could.
There is a powerful
biological drive,
at times, almost
impossible to resist.
Species are driven
by these urges
in order to survive.
But isn't that
why we have minds--
to look beyond biological
urges, to consider
their consequences?
If I'm going to ask myself
to look at those consequences,
then I have to ask myself
some questions.
Am I really ready
to have a child?
Am I prepared to give that child
the attention and devotion
it deserves?
Am I capable of taking on
such a huge responsibility?
Oh, there's so much
I haven't done.
There's so much
I want to study and learn.
I'm not sure
I'm finished growing.
How could I help a child grow?
If the smaller creatures
are sexually attracted
to our subspace emissions,
then the large one
may perceive us as a rival.
That plasma burst
it sent out
might have been
aggressive posturing.
Then you'd think it would be
happy to see us leave.
Lieutenant, is there
any way we could generate
a short burst of impulse?
Enough to get us away
from this swarm?
I could try releasing power from
the impulse capacitance cells
straight into the driver coils.
Do it.
All right.
I've accessed
the capacitance cells.
I think I can give you enough
for a short burst of impulse.
We've got one shot, Captain.
You heard her, Mr. Paris.
Make the best of it.
Aye, Captain.
Initiating impulse burst...
now.
( console beeping )
Captain,
the creature is reacting.
It is approaching rapidly
on a collision course.
Evasive maneuvers, Lieutenant.
We don't have the power
for that.
The creature is accelerating.
I'm losing power.
Can't shake him.
All hands brace for impact.
Structural integrity
down to 86 percent.
I am beginning to share
Lieutenant Torres' views,
Captain.
Retaliation
may become necessary.
It's not my intention
to harm the creature.
The feeling
definitely isn't mutual.
Mr. Tuvok, launch
a class-4 probe.
Maybe that will distract
the creature long enough
for us to get away.
Aye, Captain.
Probe launched.
KIM:
Another plasma burst.
Shields are down to 64 percent.
Looks like the probe
just made him angry.
This is an aggressive life-form,
Captain.
He's only going to respond
to an aggressive stance from us.
TUVOK:
Treating the creature
as it is treating us
might be an
appropriate response.
We ram him.
Precisely.
It's probably the
response he expects.
Captain,
shields are at 47 percent.
Any more of this and the hull
will start to buckle.
Mr. Paris, use
maneuvering thrusters.
Set a course
toward the creature.
Give him a bump
to get his attention.
Aye, Captain.
Engaging thrusters.
The creature is not retreating,
Captain.
He's just hitting us
back harder.
Let's try this.
Detonate a field
of photon charges
between Voyager
and the creature.
Maybe the shock wave will
let him know we mean business.
Captain, if I may.
Maybe we're going
about this backwards.
Yes, Commander?
Every aggressive move we make
results in a more aggressive
move by the creature.
If we're not prepared
to use extreme force
to destroy him,
we need to rethink our actions.
I'm listening.
If we're right that the creature
is responding to us
as a sexual rival,
we might try behaving
in a submissive way.
That may appease him. We'd be
acknowledging that he's dominant
and that we're no match for him.
How do we do that?
We tried to move
away slowly.
He wouldn't let us leave.
Maybe we need to mimic
the behavior
of the smaller creatures.
We saw them rolling over
and changing color.
KIM:
If we vent plasma residue,
that might make us look blue.
Mr. Paris, do we
have enough power
to take Voyager
into a roll?
I think so.
All right.
Let's give this a try.
Mr. Kim, start venting
plasma residue.
Mr. Paris,
roll the ship.
Full power to
inertial dampers.
He's not responding at all. It's
not working.
KIM: Wait a minute, Captain.
What is it?
One of the small creatures
is detaching
from the starboard nacelle.
And another one.
They're all
letting go.
It appears we have lost
our sex appeal, Captain.
Good piloting, Lieutenant.
Now, let's see
if we can move away
without
any interference.
I can give you
enough thruster power
to sustain a speed
of 100 kph.
Acknowledged.
Good work, Commander. In the
future,
if I have any questions
about mating behavior,
I'll know where to go.
( knife chopping )
Can I help?
No.
Thanks.
Is something wrong?
No, no, nothing.
You've been very quiet
ever since I decided
not to conceive.
It was your choice.
I respect that.
Neelix...
I think you're disappointed.
I think...
once I decided
to become a father,
I was looking forward to it.
But I'll get over it.
Maybe you won't have
to get over it.
Just wait a little longer.
But I thought...
this was the only time.
The Doctor believes
the elogium was false,
brought on by
the electrophoretic field
that those life-forms created.
So there's a possibility
that I might be able
to go through it again
at the right age.
You mean, we might still
be able to have a daughter?
Or a son.
No.
I've thought about it.
A daughter, definitely.
One who looks just like you.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 48921.3.
I continue to wonder
about the issue of procreation
aboard the ship.
Certainly, it's wrong
to interfere
with the private lives
and decisions of the crew.
Yet I remain concerned
about the environment
we could provide
for any child born here.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Yes, Ensign. What can I do for
you?
I'm sorry
to disturb you, Captain,
but I thought...
I thought I
should inform you
of my physical condition.
Your physical condition?
Well, we'd been trying
for months.
I wasn't even sure
until a few days ago.
My husband is still
at Deep Space 9.
He doesn't even know.
We were only
supposed to be out
two or three weeks.
Wildman...
are you pregnant?
I know this isn't the best place
to have a baby, but...
it's all I have left...
of my husband.
Well...
congratulations, Ensign.