JANEWAY:
Voyager to Shuttlecraft Drake.
Prepare for
emergency transport.
Mr. Kim, can you hear me?
We're attempting
to lock onto you.
Harry?
WOMAN:
Hey, it's time to wake up.
What's wrong?
Libby...
Yes?
This can't be happening.
What's wrong with you?
Libby, it's really
you, isn't it?
Come on. You're going
to be late.
What?
You have a meeting.
0900, remember?
You've only been obsessing
about it for a week.
I don't want
Lieutenant Lasca blaming me
because you weren't on time
for the biggest meeting
of your career.
Now, get dressed and I'll
make you some breakfast.
Come on.
The eggs are getting cold.
What's with you today?
The date.
What's the date?
The date?
What day is today?
49011.
So this isn't the past,
it's the present.
San Francisco.
This can't be a dream.
It's too... real.
It's too clear.
So what does that leave?
A holodeck?
A hallucination?
Some kind of trick?
The last thing I
remember was piloting
a shuttlecraft
on my way back to Voyager.
We have a long day ahead of us.
Could we play this little game
another time, please?
No...
you can't be Libby.
It's not possible.
My name is
Ensign Harry Kim
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
Where am I?
Is this some sort
of simulation?
That's not
funny, Harry.
Talking about
Voyager like that.
The memorial service was
only two months ago.
Danny was your
best friend.
How could you joke
about that?
Danny... Danny Byrd?
I'm done with
this conversation.
Go to work.
I'll see you
tonight.
What is going on?
MAN:
Harry!
Coming right up.
Here you go.
Vulcan mocha,
extra sweet.
Thanks.
So, today's
the big day, huh?
What do you mean?
You know, the meeting.
The new ship
you're designing.
And don't forget, you promised
to bring me a model.
And I'm going to hang it
right there in my window
and I'll tell everyone
"Harry Kim,
he designed that ship.
He came into my shop
every morning."
Look, I know this is going
to sound a little funny
but how long have I been
coming to this coffee shop?
How long?
Well, let's see.
Since you left the academy.
How long is that?
Eight... eight months.
Eight months?
And you've seen me every day?
Well, not every day.
You like to sleep
late on Sunday.
But if had your fiancée,
I'd sleep late too.
Fiancée?
We're getting married?
Ahh, yes. There were
many mornings I woke up
I said the same thing to myself
when I was about to be married
but don't worry. It will pass.
I don't think you've ever had
a morning quite like this one.
Hey, Harry! You ready to go?
Um... where?
Very funny. Come on.
We better get moving
if we're going to catch
the transport
to headquarters.
I'm not sure I can go.
I'm not feeling very well.
Maybe I should just go home.
Come on, come on.
It's just a case
of the jitters.
You'll do just fine.
Relax, Harry.
If all goes well, you'll walk
out of this room a lieutenant.
Let me see that
warp coil schematic.
The what?
The coil diagram...
the one with the new
plasma flow equations.
I forgot
to bring it.
Forgot?
Harry, we need
that diagram to show
that we've worked out
the dilithium fracture problem.
I'm sorry.
Well, we'll just
have to improvise.
Good morning.
I have a meeting at 1100 with
the head of Starfleet Security.
She doesn't like
to be kept waiting.
Let's get this underway.
Lieutenant Lasca?
Thank you, admiral.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you are looking at
the new runabout Yellowstone.
It's equipped with
tetrion plasma warp nacelles
and designed for a variety
of mission profiles.
Yes, Lieutenant, I've looked
over your specifications.
It's an interesting design,
but how do you propose
to address the dilithium
fracture problem?
Tetrion plasma
tends to disrupt subspace.
LASCA:
I'm actually glad you
asked that question, sir.
We've been working on the
problem for several weeks
and I think you'll see
that we have found an answer.
I'd like to
introduce you
to the engineer
who designed
these new warp engines.
And, I might add,
he is the most promising
young engineer
to come out of the academy
in a long time.
Ensign Harry Kim.
Harry.
STRICKLER:
Is there a problem,
Ensign?
Actually, sir, there is.
Come on, Harry.
Pull it together.
We've been waiting
for this for six months.
Ensign, are you ill?
Yes, sir.
I'm very ill.
I would like to...
continue this presentation
at a later date.
Well, unfortunately, Ensign,
I'm leaving
for a three-week tour
of the Cardassian border
in a few days.
It will have to wait
until after then.
Harry... you better be dying.
I guess I'm pretty good.
Computer,
display my service record.
"Graduated Starfleet Academy,
stardate 47918.
"Requested duty
on U.S.S. Voyager.
"Request... denied.
"Requested transfer to Starfleet
engineering corps.
"Transfer approved.
"Starship design specialist.
"Awarded the Cochrane
Medal of Excellence
for Outstanding Advances
in Warp Theory."
Computer, access Starfleet
Science Academy database.
Have there been
any temporal anomalies
in the space-time continuum
reported in the last 48 hours?
COMPUTER:
Negative.
No temporal anomalies
have been reported.
Computer,
has there been any contact
with the starship Voyager
Since it was lost
in the badlands?
Information on U.S.S. Voyager
is classified.
Security clearance
level three or above
is required to access files.
No problem. It's my ship.
Or at least I thought it was.
Security authorization
accepted.
Last recorded contact
with U.S.S. Voyager
prior to its disappearance
was on stardate 48307.5.
Access Voyager crew manifest.
Who was the operations officer
on board?
Ensign Daniel Byrd.
Danny.
Harry.
What are you doing
back so early?
Oh. Hi.
I wasn't feeling too well,
so I decided to come home.
You don't look
sick to me.
Coming home for a little
visit with Libby, are we?
Ah, to be young.
Don't worry. I'll
keep your secret.
Thanks.
Listen, I know this is
going to sound strange
but I forgot to look
at the street number
when I left this morning
and I don't remember
which building I live in.
Could you...?
Tell you
where you live?
You're not playing
some kind of a prank
on your old pal
Cosimo, are you?
No. Like I said...
I haven't been
feeling well and...
everything's
kind of foggy.
Okay, okay, okay.
Well, you live
right over there--
fourth floor,
apartment 4-G.
Thanks.
Harry.
Don't look
so concerned.
Everything's
going to work out.
You have a wonderful job,
a beautiful fiancée.
Everything is
going to be fine.
Trust me.
Hmm?
( door closes )
LIBBY:
Hello? Who's there?
It's just me, Libby.
Harry?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
You feel
a little warm.
God, you're tense.
Why don't you tell me
what happened today.
Nothing.
Everything.
I'm not sure
what happened.
Harry...
forget about work.
Try to relax.
You're home now.
What can I do to help?
Just...
tell me you love me.
( chuckles )
I tell you that
every day.
Aren't you getting
sick of hearing it?
No.
In fact...
pretend I haven't
heard you say it
in a long time.
Pretend that we haven't
seen each other for months.
Okay.
I love you, Harry.
Welcome home.
So...
if we haven't seen
each other for months...
where have you been?
Oh...
on a starship.
Thousands of
light years away.
A mission?
Yeah.
We got a little lost.
Aww.
Sounds lonely.
You can't imagine.
Tell me something.
Hm?
You didn't stop at Risa
along the way, did you?
No.
No pleasure planet
excursions, I'm afraid.
You thought about me
the whole time?
Every day.
Every nanosecond.
Do me a favor.
Hm?
Don't ever
leave me again.
"Orlando, Parsons, Peterson,
Platt, Porter..."
Wait a minute-- Paris.
Where's Tom Paris?
Computer, access
service record
of Starfleet officer
Thomas Eugene Paris.
"Convicted of treason.
"Sentenced to 18 months
"at the New Zealand
penal settlement.
"Paroled on stardate 48702.
Last reported whereabouts:
Marseille, France."
Harry?
It's 4:00
in the morning.
What are you doing?
Oh, I couldn't sleep.
So I thought I'd
catch up on some work.
When are you
going to tell me
what's going on?
There's nothing going on, okay?
You're not a very good liar,
Harry.
You've been acting strange
all day
and I'm not the only one
who's worried about you.
Lieutenant Lasca called
this afternoon.
He said he's never
seen you so agitated.
So don't tell me there's
nothing going on.
Libby...
it's hard to
explain right now
and I do want to tell you,
but I need you to trust me.
I do trust you.
I love you.
That's why
I'm marrying you.
I would hope you would
have the same trust in me.
All right.
This...
this is going to sound
a little crazy
from your perspective
but I am not who
you think I am.
Oh?
All of this--
it's not supposed
to be happening.
I don't belong here.
If you're having
second thoughts
about getting married,
why didn't you just say so?
You don't understand.
What I'm trying to say is...
I'm from another reality.
Another reality?
That's right.
Harry, you're starting
to scare me.
I know.
I'm scared too.
Maybe you should talk
to a counselor...
a neurologist.
There may be something
wrong with you.
I will.
But there's someone else
I need to see first.
Where are
you going?
Marseille, France.
What for?
I've got to see Paris.
But, you just said...
you were going
to Marseille.
It's a long story.
Trust me.
Okay?
Okay.
MAN:
Hey, watch it, will you?
I'm trying to set up
a shot here.
Tom.
Who the hell are you?
You don't know
me, do you?
Sure. We were at the academy
together, right?
No.
Oh. Well, it must
have been the Exeter.
We served on
the Exeter together?
Try Voyager.
Ah... Voyager.
Well, sorry to disappoint
you, but...
...I never set foot
on that ship.
I can't say that I'm sorry
considering what
happened to it.
You know about the mission
to the badlands?
Oh, yeah.
Captain Janeway asked if
I'd help her track down
that Maquis ship
in exchange for an early
release from the penal colony.
But you said no?
Are you kidding?
I said yes.
Sounded better than
Starfleet rehab.
Anyway, I got as far
as Deep Space Nine, where I got
into a bar fight with a Ferengi
and I was thrown
into the brig
by a very unpleasant
shapeshifter.
Janeway tried
to get me released
but my parole was revoked
by Starfleet Command.
Voyager left without me.
That Ferengi, was he trying
to sell you Lobi crystals?
Yeah.
How do you know
about that?
Because I was there--
In my reality, anyway.
Tom, I know this is going
to sound crazy,
but I was on Voyager,
and so were you.
You never got into a bar
fight with that Ferengi.
You stopped him from
selling me Lobi crystals.
And you did lead us
into the badlands.
You're right.
That does sound crazy.
Something's happened.
Somehow reality has
been changed--
a temporal anomaly,
an alien influence--
I can't explain how.
All I know is
that it's true.
I was in a shuttlecraft
heading back to Voyager
and then I woke up here,
on earth.
What is it you want?
Come with me to
Starfleet Headquarters.
Help me run
a computer simulation
of what happened
on that shuttle.
You're the best pilot
I've ever seen.
And if anyone can
figure it out, it's you.
( snickering )
( laughing )
God...
You... you had me there
for a minute.
You really did,
but then you blew it.
What are you talking about?
You're not getting me
to set foot inside
Starfleet headquarters.
So you tell whatever admiral
or captain who sent you
that I'm not interested in
being another pawn in
one of their games.
It's not a game!
Oh, it isn't?
Oh, that's a shame.
I like games.
You once told me
that you used to treat life
like one big game--
Rules, players.
Winners, losers.
You never took
any of it seriously
until you lost.
You know, you're starting
to annoy me.
You also told me you were afraid
of what would happen to you
if you didn't take
Captain Janeway up on her offer.
Now I see why.
What do you see...
Ensign?
A loser...
and a drunk.
I guess in this reality
that's all you'll ever be.
What's going on?
Harry, just relax.
Why does everyone say relax
when they're about to do
something terrible?
Starfleet knows
what you've been doing.
Which is what, exactly?
Breaking into classified files
using forged
security access codes.
I haven't forged anything.
And I can explain.
That's why we're here.
We're going to take you back
to Starfleet Headquarters.
They want to ask you
a few questions.
Harry, please--
just go with them.
Tell them what
you told me.
Everything will be alright.
I don't think I have a choice
at the moment.
I'll see you later.
You claim to have Voyager
security protocols
because you were
an officer on Voyager.
Yes, sir.
Lost in the Delta Quadrant.
And Ensign Daniel Byrd--
you say that he's taken
your place on that ship?
Yes, sir.
And this is all because...
reality has been
changed somehow?
Yes, sir.
But you don't have
a single shred of evidence
to back up
your claims.
( door opens )
Harry, I don't
doubt for a minute
that you believe you're
telling the truth
but we have to consider
all the possibilities.
Like what?
Like you could
be delusional
or you could have had your
memory centers altered
so that you think what
you're saying is the truth
or you could be an alien
masquerading as Harry Kim.
That's crazy.
I am Harry Kim.
Check my DNA
if you don't believe me.
Run a microcellular scan of
my cerebral cortex to see
my memory's been altered.
Everything
I'm saying is true.
Mr. Kim, why did you travel
to Marseille, France
this morning?
I went to look up an old friend.
You have
poor taste in friends.
Thomas Paris
is a convicted traitor
and a Maquis
sympathizer.
Now, what did you
talk about with him?
I tried to tell him
what's happened.
I wanted his help.
His help?
To run a shuttle simulation?
Why?
To figure out how I got here,
and how I can get back.
There must be temporal anomaly
somewhere, or...
You think I'm a spy, don't you?
You think I'm working
for the Maquis.
We're here to find
the truth, Ensign.
whatever that might be.
That's it.
I'm not answering
any more questions
until I have legal counsel.
You have that right.
Harry, we want to help you,
but try to understand.
What you are telling us
doesn't make much sense.
All we know so far is
that you have been seen
talking with a
Maquis criminal
and you've broken into
classified Starfleet records.
Until there is something else--
something concrete
those are the fact
in this case
and you have to admit
the facts look pretty bad.
STRICKLER:
We will be monitoring
your movements
until further notice.
I believe you know
the restrictions.
No off-world travel,
and if you tamper
with the anklet
security will be
immediately alerted
and you will be
formally charged.
Do you understand?
Yes, admiral.
We'll be spending a lot
time together, Ensign,
and I assure you,
we will get
to the bottom of this.
You're dismissed.
Troubles, Harry?
You could say that.
Let's have some coffee.
I was sent here to watch you--
to make sure
that you were all right.
But now it's clear
that you are not.
Who are you?
We exist in what
you would call
a temporal inversion fold
in the space-time matrix.
It's not necessary
to understand.
It only matters that
there was an accident.
Your shuttle intersected
one of our time-streams
and... boom!
A few things were altered
as the result
of the accident.
History and events
were scrambled a bit
and you ended up here.
Well, you've got
to get me back.
Ah...
we don't know how.
What?
We only know that
an accident occurred.
We don't know how or why.
Well, that's not good enough.
There's got to be
something we can do.
Where is this
time-stream of yours?
Maybe I can use it to get back.
Mmm...
the time-stream weaves through
the galaxy like a thread.
I could show you how to find it
and you could try to recreate
the conditions that existed
before the accident
and fly back into it,
but there's no guarantee
what will happen to you
if you do.
What do you mean?
Well, you may be able
to change reality again
but there's no way to predict
how it would change.
You could end up at any point
in the space-time continuum.
You might return to
your original reality
or you might
find yourself
a billion years in the future
or at some time
before sentient life
even existed on your planet.
I guess I'll have
to take that chance
because somehow
I have to get back.
Are you so sure?
This is a pretty good
place for you, Harry.
You have a wonderful
job with Starfleet,
a beautiful woman
who loves you.
Why be so quick to turn your
back on all this?
Maybe this is your... fate?
Isn't that the word
your people use?
That thing which
was meant to be? Hmm?
Seems to me you're
actually a very lucky man.
What about Danny Byrd?
He isn't so lucky.
And Tom Paris?
Fate wasn't so kind to him.
No.
It isn't supposed
to be this way.
I'm supposed to be on Voyager
in the Delta Quadrant,
and that's where
I have to go.
Very well.
This will tell you
where the time-stream
intersects this
region of space.
That's as much
as I can do for you.
Thanks.
Good luck,
Harry Kim of Voyager.
You're going to need it.
Unless, of course,
you decide to stay.
In which case I'll see you
in the morning, same time--
Vulcan mocha, extra sweet.
( chuckling )
Libby...
I didn't hear you come in.
Obviously.
You're in enough trouble
as it is.
What do you want them to do,
put you in prison?
No.
I'm just trying to get back
to where I belong.
Where you belong.
You used to say you
belonged here with me.
But I guess everything's
changed, hasn't it?
Look...
I know the last few days
must have been pretty
tough on you--
Do you?!
Do you really know
what it's like
when the person you love
suddenly changes?
It's still me--
the guy who was
in your seat at
the Ktarian music festival.
The guy who took three weeks
to work up the courage
to ask you out.
The guy who still wakes up
in the middle of the night
and says your name out loud
hoping you'll answer back.
But if you're really Harry,
you wouldn't
be trying so hard
to get away from me.
I'm not trying
to get away from you.
I love you.
And I promise you I want to stay
here more than anything.
But I can't.
I don't understand.
I don't understand any of this.
I don't think
anybody knows me
as well as you do.
So you of all
people should know
that once I've made up
my mind about something
I can't let it go.
In some ways...
it'd be a lot easier
to forget about Voyager
just settle in here
and build a life...
but that wouldn't be me.
You wouldn't be
getting the Harry Kim
you fell in love with.
Does that make any sense?
( beeping )
The tampering alarm.
Security will be
here any second.
I'd better go.
I promise you, I'm going
to try to get back.
It may take a while
and I may not make it,
but I swear I will try.
Sorry.
( grunting )
Hold it!
Get up!
PARIS:
Excuse me.
There goes my bank shot.
What are you doing here?
Helping out a friend.
Let's go.
So how did you find me?
I still have a few
friends at Starfleet.
They told me you were
in some serious trouble.
Yeah. Starfleet thinks
I'm a Maquis spy.
I know the feeling.
Those security anklets
really chafe, don't they?
You're the last person
I expected to help me.
Let's just say
it's been a long time
since anybody gave a damn
about my future, including me.
I don't know if I'm
supposed to be on Voyager
like you've told me.
But it sounds a whole lot better
than the life I have here.
I'm willing to take
my chances, Ensign.
Call me Harry.
You always did.
It won't be long
before they find us.
We'd better keep moving.
Wait, I found a way to
get back to my reality.
The problem is I'll need
a ship to do it.
I think I have access
to a runabout,
but I'm going to have to break
it out of spacedock.
Sounds to me like
you need a pilot.
Know anyone who's qualified?
I know someone who used
to be pretty good
and if I'm not mistaken,
he still knows a few tricks.
I have an office at
Starfleet headquarters.
I think we can access
the runabout launch codes
from there.
Site-to-site
transporter.
With friends like mine,
you never know when
it'll come in handy.
Where's your office?
Main complex, level 6,
subsection 47.
I can beam us in, but we'll
only have a few minutes
before security starts
kicking down the door.
Let's do it.
So, Harry, once we're
on board the runabout,
what's the plan?
The alien said that
if I recreate
the conditions
of the accident
and fly into
the time-stream,
there's a chance I might be able
to get back into my reality.
Might?
He couldn't give me
any guarantees.
Security's just been alerted
to an unauthorized transport
in the building.
It'll take them another
20 seconds
to track it to this office.
How are you coming?
Almost there.
I've bypassed
the runabout
security lock-outs.
They're onto us.
We got to go.
Hold on. I've almost got it.
Now!
Overriding
initialization codes.
Main power
coming on-line.
Let's get
those engines going.
Powering up
main fusion reactor.
COMPUTER:
Intruder alert.
Unauthorized launch
in progress.
The space door is closing.
Warp core and main
propulsion are on-line.
Releasing docking clamps,
moorings cleared.
Here we go.
We're clear.
I'm entering
the coordinates
of the time-stream
into the main computer.
Adjusting course to match,
going to full impulse.
We've got a starship
on our tail, nebula class.
I'll try to lose them, Harry,
but they're a lot faster
than we are.
MAN:
Attention runabout Yellowstone.
Power down your engines
or we will open fire.
They're going to try to do
everything they can to stop us.
They think we're trying
to steal this prototype.
They're closing
to 5,000 kilometers.
Shields down to 70%.
50%.
29%.
I thought you said this ship
was new and improved.
It is.
But it looks like they haven't
finished working on
the defensive systems.
In fact,
some of the safety interlocks
aren't even in place.
A few more of those hits
and I don't--
We're losing
antimatter containment.
Attempting to
stabilize the field.
We're approaching the
coordinates of the time-stream.
The containment field
is weakening.
We could be looking
at a core breach.
The ship's closing
to 3,000 kilometers.
If we can't
shake them off,
maybe we can slow
them down a little.
This runabout
is equipped with
tetrion plasma warp nacelles.
So?
Tetrion plasma emits
multiflux gamma radiation.
It disrupts subspace.
We could vent
the warp plasma.
The second they hit
the plasma cloud,
their engines would stall,
It would give us a few seconds
of breathing room.
Exactly.
Unlocking the warp
drive manifold.
Venting drive plasma.
Any second...
They've dropped
to one-tenth impulse.
Our containment field's
at critical.
We'd better hurry.
All right, let's recreate
my shuttle accident.
I think I was traveling
at 140,000 KPH.
You think?
Look, that was another lifetime.
I'm doing the best I can.
Increasing speed
to 140,000 KPH.
Now, I also remember
running a polaron scan.
The scanning beam
was sweeping at a radius
of half a million
kilometers.
No, wait...
a quarter million.
Activating polaron scan.
That should do it.
Approaching coordinates.
Impact in four...
three...
two...
Did we miss it?
We passed through
the coordinates,
but the runabout
was unaffected.
The starship
has repowered its engines.
They'll be here
in under a minute.
I have to get into
that time-stream.
Wait a minute.
I'm forgetting something.
The emergency transport.
The last thing
I remember hearing
was Captain Janeway's
com voice.
She said she was trying to beam
me off the shuttle.
That's it. I've got
to beam off the ship.
Are you crazy?
We have to recreate
all the conditions
of the accident--
including that one.
We just lost
antimatter containment.
25 seconds
to core breach.
I've locked onto
the time-stream.
Get on the
transporter pad.
Not yet, the core's breaching.
We've got to shut
it down first.
There's no time!
That ship'll be here
in another 30 seconds.
In 15 seconds, this ship
is going to explode.
You'll be killed.
Look, if you're right,
then things will be changed
back to the way they're
supposed to be,
and you'll find me
back on Voyager.
And if I'm wrong,
if this doesn't work
you'll be blown up
right here.
Go!
JANEWAY:
Voyager to Shuttlecraft Drake.
Prepare
for emergency transport.
Mr. Kim, can you hear me?
We're attempting
to lock on to you... Harry?
Kim here, captain.
Harry, we need you
to drop your shields.
Stand by.
Shields down, captain.
Lieutenant.
The anomaly is sending out
heavy subspace distortions.
I can't get
a positive lock on him.
The hull is starting
to buckle under the stress.
He won't survive much longer.
Tuvok, can you boost
the transporter signal?
Negative. The signal is
at maximum gain.
Ten seconds to hull breach.
He's just out
of reach.
B'elanna, can you tie
the transporter
directly into the main
deflector dish.
Use it to extend
the signal.
I'll try.
Hull breach in progress.
We've got him, Captain.
Mr. Chakotay,
analyze the sensor logs.
I want to know what
happened out there.
Aye, captain.
Voyager to
transporter room two.
Are you all right,
Mr. Kim?
KIM:
I think so, captain.
Is Lieutenant Paris there?
Yes, he's here. Why?
It's a long story.
I look forward
to hearing it.
I'll be in my ready room.
We think
your shuttlecraft
was caught in some kind
of temporal anomaly.
A time-stream?
Yes, you could
call it that.
I've already been
briefed, commander.
Welcome back.
Kind of a rough ride, huh?
What is it, Harry?
I owe you one.