( majestic theme playing )
Hello?
Anybody here?
Neelix?
ALL:
Surprise!
Happy birthday,
my sweet.
Happy birthday, Kes.
Imagine. Two years
old today.
If you ask me, you don't
look a day over one.
( all laughing )
Why was everyone hiding?
Oh, it's an old Earth custom
called a surprise party.
Sorry if we
startled you.
No, I liked it.
It was very exhilarating.
NEELIX:
Now,
how about a glass
of my special birthday punch?
Garçon?
On the rocks or straight up?
Doctor,
I'm so glad
you're here.
My new bartender.
Handsome, isn't he?
I'm here in an official
capacity, of course--
in case of
a medical emergency.
Emergency?
Surprises have been
known to cause
acute hyperventilation,
esophageal spasms
and in extreme cases,
even coronary arrest.
One can never be too careful.
( accordion playing
in background)
( chuckling)
I've completed the sensor
diagnostic, Lieutenant.
All systems are
fully operational.
Very good, Ensign.
And I've recalibrated
the accelerometer relays.
Acknowledged.
Is there anything else
I can do for you, sir?
I presume
this notable impatience
is due to your desire
to attend the festivities
in Holodeck 2.
Yes, sir.
May I remind you
that your duty shift
does not officially terminate
for another 34 minutes.
However,
I believe
the holodeck power conduits
would benefit
from a routine inspection.
Yes, sir, I'll get right on it.
All stop.
Mr. Kim.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What is that?
Magnify.
I'm afraid
that holodeck inspection
will have to wait, Ensign.
Wait till you taste this cake.
Seven layers
of Jimbalian fudge,
and the icing is made
from pureed l'maki nuts--
Kes' favorite.
Now make a wish and
blow out the candles.
Well, what do I wish for?
Anything your petite coeur
desires, ma chérie,
and with a figure like hers,
she'll probably get it, too.
( all giggling)
Okay, I wish for--
Don't tell us.
The wish has to be a secret
if it's going to come true.
( accordion playing
in background )
( crowd applauding )
I hate to interrupt this
tender little moment, Tommy boy,
but don't you think
it's about time we shot a rack?
In a minute.
Birthday gifts are also
an Earth tradition.
Oh, thank you, Tom.
You didn't have to.
Hey, who am I
to fly in the face
of tradition?
Tom, it's beautiful.
It must have cost you a week's
worth of replicator rations.
Two weeks, actually,
but who's counting?
I'm just glad
you like it.
May I?
Oh. It's lovely.
You see, it's a locket.
You put little photographs
in here.
It keeps
the people you love
close to your heart.
Thank you.
Did you see that?
See what?
He...
he...
he did a lovely wrapping job,
don't you think?
TUVOK ( on communicator):
Bridge to Janeway.
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
Captain, we've encountered
an unusual phenomenon...
( echoing):
phenomenon... phenomenon...
phenomenon...
( distorted):
( louder):
phenomenon...
phenomenon... phenomenon...
( majestic theme playing )
TUVOK ( loudly):
Phenomenon... phenomenon...
( loudly):
What is going on, Lieutenant?
It might simply be
a localized malfunction,
but I've never heard
anything like it.
My guess is...
( noise stops)
It's a problem with
the com system itself.
Janeway to Bridge.
Get down to Engineering
and run a diagnostic.
I'm afraid we're going to have
to cut your party short, Kes.
Stations, everyone. Let's move.
But-- but--
What about
the Jimbalian fudge cake?
Save me a slice, won't you?
( sighs softly)
KIM:
These readings indicate
the space ahead of us
is literally changing shape.
A best guess is it's some type
of spatial
distortion wave.
Is the anomaly responsible
for the com system malfunction?
I think so. It's generating
intense pulses of EM radiation,
and if we don't
get out of its way,
it's going to intercept us
in less than ten minutes.
Acknowledged.
Full reverse, Ensign.
WOMAN:
Aye, sir.
We can't go backwards, either,
Mr. Tuvok.
The distortion has completely
surrounded us, like a ring.
If we cannot go around it,
then we will have
to go through it.
There's no telling
what that would do to the ship.
From what you have told me,
Ensign,
the distortion ring will make
contact with us momentarily
whether we attempt
to pass through it or not.
I prefer to minimize the amount
of time that contact lasts.
Shields at maximum.
Warp three. Engage.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The distortion ring
has collapsed the warp field.
Engines are off-line.
Find the Captain
and inform her of our status.
Yes, sir.
Ensign Kim, I've
been trying to report
a problem in the gym,
but the com system
seems to be down.
We've encountered
a spatial distortion.
It knocked out several systems.
Maybe that's why
the gym was cold.
Cold?
I didn't notice it at first,
I was working out so hard.
Then I realized it was
under 10 degrees C.
The environmental controls
didn't respond to my commands
and neither did the com system.
Engines are off-line, too.
I'm looking for the Captain
to let her know what's going on.
Should I report
to my duty station?
Might not be a bad idea.
Until we find out
exactly what's going on,
everybody should be on standby.
I'll round up
my security team.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The first thing I want to do
when we get to the Bridge
is establish a remote com link
to Engineering.
I want to know exactly
what's going on.
Aye, Captain.
Where are we?
Deck 4.
( sighs)
If the com system's
malfunctioning,
the computer could be
misreading our voice commands.
That might explain why it took
us here instead of the Bridge.
We'd better try setting
the controls manually.
Did you enjoy your first
surprise party, sweeting?
It was wonderful.
Thank you.
I thought you'd like it:
the cake, the presents.
What was your favorite part?
I suppose what
I liked best
was that all
my friends were there.
Ah, that was nice,
wasn't it?
And don't forget
that beautiful necklace
Tom Paris gave you.
Do you really like it?
Oh, why wouldn't
I like it?
Paris obviously has
excellent taste.
I was afraid you might be
a little jealous.
Who, me?
Ha, ha. Oh,
don't be silly.
Are you sure?
You, my dearest,
have seen the last
of that green-eyed pus hog
called jealousy.
I'm glad.
Of course, Paris did
replicate that locket,
whereas I baked the Jimbalian
fudge cake from scratch.
( chuckles)
These aren't my quarters.
Did we take a wrong
turn somewhere?
I was just
following you.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( crowd chattering )
Is everything all right,
Lieutenant?
This isn't Engineering.
And have someone
take a look
at the turbolift voice
receptors, Commander.
Aye, Captain.
This is Engineering.
What's going
on here?
Looks like we're dealing
with more than just
a com system malfunction.
Computer, Bridge.
Baxter, what are
you doing here?
I wish I knew.
I'm trying to get
to the cargo bay.
And I'm trying to get
to Engineering.
I can't find the cargo bay,
and I can't find
my security team.
I've been wandering around
for about ten minutes.
Well, at least I
know I'm not crazy...
unless we both are.
No. Something very strange
is going on.
Ensign Kim said we'd encountered
a spatial distortion.
Did he say what kind?
No, and he went to find
the Captain.
The Captain is on her
way to the Bridge,
but if she's having
the same trouble we are,
who knows if she
can get there.
( sighs)
I'm going to keep trying
to get to Engineering.
Good luck.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( accordion playing )
The holodeck again.
Aha!
This is infuriating.
Ah, stop playing
games, mon chéri.
I know why you keep
coming back to work
even though your
bartending shift is over.
Ha, ha. It's to see
me, of course.
How many times
do I have to tell you, madam?
Oh!
I am a doctor, not a bartender.
Of course,
you are. Ha, ha.
( accordion playing
in background)
Doc?
Ensign Kim.
I was just, uh...
Playing doctor.
( clearing throat)
Hi.
( whispering):
DOCTOR:
The Captain and the others
went to investigate
the phenomenon
Mr. Tuvok reported.
So all of you heard his report
before the com system failed?
Only a fraction of it.
Well, I'm sure Tuvok's filled
them in with the rest by now.
What are you still doing
on the holodeck, besides
playing doctor,
that is?
For your information,
I have been attempting
to transfer myself
back to Sick Bay,
but each time I try,
I reappear here.
That's strange.
DOCTOR:
Not to mention
extremely irritating.
I can't seem to shut down Mr.
Paris' holo-program either.
Computer, end holodeck
program Paris 3.
( computer beeps)
Computer, arch.
( computer beeps )
KIM:
Either the holo-emitters
are malfunctioning,
or the computer's not accepting
voice commands.
I'm sorry, Doctor, I don't have
time to help you right now.
Wait just a minute.
Hmm?
Where do you think
you're going?
I've got to get back to
the Bridge. We're in a crisis.
All the more reason I should
be back in Sick Bay.
I'm sure that the Captain
and the others
will be able to do without you
for a few more minutes.
I guess you're right.
I'll have a look
at the holo-controls.
( sighs)
Kyoto's quarters.
Nicoletti.
Hargrove.
Ayala.
None of those are anywhere
near my quarters.
This is Deck 8. That's where
your quarters are.
But Hargrove and Ayala
are on Deck 7.
Nicoletti is on 4,
and I think Kyoto is on 6.
How do you know where
everyone's quarters are?
I just remember.
Remember from what?
Have you been
in all their quarters?
Of course not.
The point is, those quarters
can't all be on the same deck.
Well, see for yourself.
This can't be.
Perhaps, sweeting,
your memory
isn't as reliable
as you think.
This is impossible.
I know Hargrove
is on 7.
Why Hargrove?
What?
Why are you so sure
about Hargrove's quarters?
What makes him... so special?
He's not special.
I just remember
where his quarters are.
This way.
It has to be this way.
( grunts)
( growls softly)
( suspenseful theme playing )
Harry.
B'Elanna, shouldn't you
be in Engineering?
What are you
doing here?
Just answer one question,
Starfleet.
Where is here?
What?
Where am I?
Outside Holodeck 2.
Are you feeling okay?
I have been walking in circles
for the past 20 minutes
trying to get to Engineering.
NEELIX:
Kes, my sweet,
you have many
wonderful attributes.
Your sense of direction
is not one of them. I...
Oh, uh, Harry, B'Elanna,
maybe you can help us.
I know you'll find
this hard to believe,
but we can't seem to find
Kes' quarters.
( door opens )
I don't suppose
anyone here knows
the way to the Bridge?
( suspenseful theme playing )
Let me get this straight--
this distortion ring
has completely immobilized us.
We have
no means of communication
with the Bridge
or any other part of the ship,
and no matter where any of us
have tried to go--
the Bridge, Engineering,
Kes' quarters--
we've all eventually
ended up here.
Right back at Deck 6.
The Bridge is on Deck 1.
Engineering is on Deck 11.
Deck 6 is halfway
in between, right?
So?
So, if we're being
surrounded by this ring,
maybe it's pushing us all
to the center of the ship.
But it's not just that
we're being led back here.
I mean, rooms are
in the wrong place.
Is it possible that
this distortion ring
is somehow changing
the layout of the ship?
There is another
possibility.
Exposure to some types
of EM radiation
has been known
to cause
hallucinations.
Perhaps it's not the ship
that's undergone changes
but rather
your perception of it.
Unfortunately,
without my medical equipment
to analyze your optic nerves,
there's no way to tell.
We'll never figure it out
sitting here.
We need more information
about this phenomenon--
sensor readings,
computer analyses.
We have to find a way
back to the Bridge.
If we can't get back on foot
or on the turbolift,
maybe we can rig
a site-to-site transport--
beam ourselves
to the Bridge.
We'd have to get
to a transporter room first.
Or to Engineering.
Wherever that is.
When we tried to go
to the Bridge,
one of the places
the turbolift took us
was Engineering.
Maybe if we repeat our steps,
it'll take us back there.
It's worth a shot.
Lieutenant Paris,
you're with Torres.
Maybe we can get to the Bridge
through a Jefferies tube.
If I remember my ship specs
correctly,
there should be an emergency
access conduit which leads
directly from this deck to
Deck 1, right behind the Bridge.
I'd like to keep trying
to get to the Bridge on foot.
If the ship has been
reconfigured somehow, I can get
a deck-by-deck picture of what
it looks like as I go.
What's going to keep you
from getting lost?
I'll get a tricorder
from the storage locker,
rig it to emit
a photoplasmic trail.
Right. We should all
get tricorders.
Set them on active scan,
gather as much information
as we can
about what's happening
to the ship.
May I request that Kes be
allowed to stay here with me?
Besides helping stave off the
predatory advances of that...
...woman, she may be able
to help me find a way
to transfer myself
back to Sick Bay.
NEELIX:
And, uh,
I'll assist
Commander Chakotay, Captain.
As you may have heard,
my tracking skills are legendary
throughout the quadrant.
That all right with you,
Commander?
Mr. Kim, I'm with you.
Let's do it.
( majestic theme playing )
KES:
Be careful.
TORRES:
Are you sure
this is how you
got there before?
Relax, will you?
So far,
we're right on schedule.
The next stop should be...
...Voila. Engineering.
Finally.
Let's get to work.
We've got an emergency situation
on board ship.
I don't have time to go into
details, but you're all
to remain at your posts
until otherwise notified,
whether or not
your duty shifts are over.
Ensign, prepare to configure
transporter systems
for a site-to-site transport.
I've got to reset
the pattern buffer controls.
In the meantime, why don't you
check the targeting scanners?
Crewman...
there's a-an emergency situation
aboard ship.
Just...
stay right where you are.
That's an order.
I think you handled that
very well, Lieutenant.
Commander,
I would imagine
you've had some
experience with women.
( chuckles)
Some.
Oh, come now! Ha!
A... a... a handsome man like
you.
I bet women find
you irresistible.
( clears throat)
Neelix,
what's this about?
Uh...
um... uh...
have you... uh...
have you...ever been jealous?
Of course.
You have?
I imagine most people
who have been in love
have been jealous
at one time or another.
I see!
I-It's a perfectly
normal response.
Then why...
why is it so unpleasant?
Jealousy's about the fear
of losing someone we love.
There's no pain
greater than that.
Neelix...
are you afraid you're going
to lose Kes to someone?
No.
I mean, I-I-I
don't think so.
At least, I
certainly hope not.
I-I... I just
can't seem to stop
these awful feelings.
Nothing makes us more vulnerable
than when we love someone.
We can be hurt very easily.
But I've always believed
that what you get
when you love someone
is greater than what you risk.
Commander, am I ever glad to see
you. Do you have any idea
what's going on?
Not exactly.
Well, I feel like I've been
wandering around for hours.
I can't find
the cargo bay.
Have you seen anyone else?
Any more of the crew?
Some people roaming around
like me.
A couple of times
I wound up in the Mess Hall.
There were quite
a few people there.
I suggest
you make your way back.
Tell everyone you run into
to come with you,
and all of you stay put
in the Mess Hall.
When we figure out
what's going on,
we'll let you know.
Aye, Commander.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Gentlemen.
Tuvok,
what are you doing here?
That is an interesting
question, Commander.
I am not certain
how I arrived
at this location.
You're lost, too.
Indeed.
When I received no word
from you or the Captain,
I left Lieutenant
Ayala in command
and came to look
for you myself.
Can you lead us back
to the Bridge?
I do not believe so.
When I first
realized I was lost,
I attempted to
retrace my steps,
only to find
myself here.
None of us has been able
to reach the Bridge.
In fact, Neelix and I
can't seem to get off Deck 6.
Strange. I thought
we were on Deck 3.
What was our status
when you left the Bridge?
The ring has penetrated
our shields
and is now in
direct contact
with the hull.
Then maybe it is possible
the distortions
are somehow
reconfiguring the ship.
As improbable as it sounds,
that would appear
to be the case.
Neelix, let's go.
Neelix.
I don't understand it.
We should have found the hatch
to the Bridge 10 minutes ago.
I feel like
we're crawling in circles.
But we haven't-- at least not
according to this tricorder.
( tricorder beeping)
Odd!
What is it?
A very faint
electromagnetic reading.
Now it's gone.
There it is from
another direction.
Yeah, I'm getting it, too.
It comes and goes.
Jumps from place to place.
Could it be evidence
of the ship's reconfiguration?
Possibly.
We'll have to
compare this data
with readings
the others get.
Harry?
Yes, ma'am?
I just want
you to know...
you've been one
of the bright spots
of this whole mission.
You've exceeded
any expectations
I might have had of you.
Thank you, Captain.
I... I appreciate that.
( rapid beeping)
Wait a minute.
Down there.
I think that's the conduit
leading to the Bridge.
Good work.
Maybe now we'll get
some answers.
That's the hatch,
Captain.
This should let us out
in the cargo hold
directly behind the Bridge.
It's not working.
We'd better try it
manually.
( grunting)
It's stuck.
Oh!
Oh...
Captain!
( dramatic theme playing )
( Janeway whimpering)
( grunts)
I... c-can't...
get my arm out.
Oh! Oh...
Oh...
( grunting)
I think I'm okay.
( recorder beeping, blipping )
I'm reading an intense
electromagnetic charge
on the other side of that hatch.
That must have been
what was pulling you in.
It's as if everything
on the other side
is in a state
of structural flux--
the walls, the atmosphere...
And the sequence
of those fluctuations
matches the readings
from the distortion ring.
This phenomenon isn't just
occurring in space.
It's definitely inside the ship
as well.
We're going to have to regroup
and come up with a plan
for combating this thing.
( grunts softly)
Captain, what's wrong?
I don't know.
Oh...
Oh, my eyes...
Captain?
Captain!
( groaning)
Come on, pal,
one lousy game.
I'll spot you
six balls.
I'm not programmed
to play games.
If he won't play pool
with you,
and he won't
make love to me,
then as far
as I'm concerned,
he can mop the floor.
You see these hands?
These are surgeon's hands,
created
by the most sophisticated
computer imaging technology
available.
They do not play games,
and they do not mop floors!
Then you are fired.
I will find
a new bartender.
I really wish you would.
Doctor...
Please tell me
you've had some success
in reinitializing
the holo-emitters.
I did exactly what you told me,
but it didn't work.
Of course not.
I'm starting to get worried
about Neelix. What's
taking them so long?
Ah, trust me, chérie. You are
better off without him.
All men are alike. In the end,
they always break your heart.
KIM:
Can I get some help here?
DOCTOR:
What happened to her?
She came into contact
with the spatial distortions
in the Jefferies tube.
She seemed fine
for a couple minutes,
but then she started to fade
in and out of consciousness.
I believe we should
go this way, Commander.
W-What makes
you say that?
If we are indeed trapped
in some sort of labyrinth,
then the logical course is
to systematically eliminate
all routes which do not lead us
to our desired destination.
The route that remains
will be the correct one.
Since we have been making
a series of right turns,
we should continue to do so
until we are certain
this path is not
the proper one.
There's a flaw in your logic.
How so, Commander?
You're assuming
there's a logical pattern
to this maze we're caught in,
but so far I haven't seen
any evidence of that.
Even within chaotic systems,
there is a pattern
of limited predictability.
By the time we figure
that pattern out,
these distortions may have
completely overrun the ship.
That is a possibility.
The important thing is
for at least one of us
to make it back to the Bridge.
So why don't you go your way,
and I'll go mine.
That way, we'll increase
the chances that one of us
will be successful.
As you wish, Commander.
Tell me something, Tuvok.
What does your logic tell you
about navigating a maze
that's constantly
changing shape?
( suspenseful theme playing )
Scanners check out.
Then we're ready
to give it a try.
Activate the auxiliary
pattern buffers.
Pattern buffers
activated.
Targeting the Bridge
coordinates.
Scanners locked.
( majestic theme playing )
Energize.
Would you mind moving
your foot, Tommy boy?
It's blocking my shot.
Tell me you already
made it to the Bridge,
and you've come back here
to give us a status report.
We locked on to the
Bridge coordinates,
but this is
where we ended up.
None of you
had any luck either?
Not only has no one been able
to reach the Bridge,
but the Captain
came into contact
with the spatial distortion
and is now unconscious.
CHAKOTAY:
That's not all.
We lost Neelix too.
Lost him?
He turned a corner,
and he was just gone.
We think the spatial distortions
are continuously changing
the configuration
of the corridors.
Kes must be
worried sick.
KIM:
And it isn't
just Neelix
who's missing.
Where's the rest
of the crew?
It is likely that they, too,
are trapped
in other parts of the ship,
cut off from communication and
unable to find their way out.
So, what do we do now?
This wave is obviously causing
some kind of radical
reconfiguration of the ship.
We've got to try to reverse it.
If not, we may never be
able to get to the Bridge.
How are we supposed to reverse
something we don't understand?
No matter where we go,
we end up here.
Corridors
are realigning,
rooms are
in the wrong place...
What's the pattern?
We would certainly benefit
an accurate picture of what
the ship currently looks like.
That way we would have
a better chance
of getting
where we want to go.
Maybe we could
make a map.
Ensign?
One good thing
about all the wandering
we've been doing
is that we've been collecting
a lot of tricorder data
about the structural changes
taking place.
And if we fed
all that information
into the central database,
the computer might be able
to extrapolate a schematic of
the ship as it's configured now.
What are we
waiting for?
( suspenseful theme playing )
KIM:
The computer has analyzed
all our tricorder data,
so this ought to be pretty close
to what it looks like now.
BAXTER:
It's as if the entire ship
is being compressed
and twisted.
My guess is, it's more
than just a distortion ring.
It looks like some sort
of spatial implosion
that's slowly
crushing us.
CHAKOTAY:
Look-- this part of the ship
seems unaffected.
That's Deck 6,
where we are.
Correct, Ensign. However,
the area we are occupying
will not remain
unaffected indefinitely.
How long?
Based on the rate
of implosion thus far,
I estimate the ring
will crush Deck 6
in approximately 68 minutes.
Is this implosion ring
some kind of weapon?
Are we under attack?
Who'd want
to attack us and why?
There is no clear evidence
of an intelligence
behind the phenomenon.
It is still possible
we are dealing with
a naturally occurring anomaly
which does not conform
to the known laws of physics.
It's too late to be speculating
on who or what this thing is.
The important thing now
is that we find out some way
of stopping it.
CHAKOTAY: B'Elanna's right.
It seems to me we've
got two options:
one, we find a way
to get ourselves out
of this implosion ring,
or two,
we find some way
of reversing it.
Invert the effect. Turn
the implosion into an explosion.
Exactly.
If I can get back to
Engineering, I may be able
to generate a shock pulse strong
enough to do just that.
I'd have to raise warp core
pressure to near-critical.
Starting a subatomic particle
shower all over the ship.
Which could set off
a chain reaction
that would cause not only
the ring to explode outward
but Voyager along with it.
Not if I can precisely tune
the shock pulse
to the distortion frequency
of the ring.
That will be
exceptionally difficult.
If we don't give this a try,
we're going
to get crushed anyway.
Personally, I'd rather
go down fighting.
I must remind you
that with the com system down,
we will have no effective means
of alerting the rest of the crew
to a potentially lethal
particle shower.
Do you have another suggestion,
Mr. Tuvok?
I believe it would be safer
to attempt to access
the navigational array
and from there engage thrusters
to steer us out of the ring.
Can't we try both?
It's much too dangerous
to have someone working
at the navigational array
during a shock pulse.
Besides,
this ship is so contorted,
there's no reason to expect we'd
have any navigational control.
All right, B'Elanna, let's give
your plan a shot. You--
TUVOK:
Commander Chakotay.
Yes, Lieutenant?
I must point out that in
my many years of experience
as Captain Janeway's
technical officer,
she often demonstrated
a tendency to follow--
In case you hadn't noticed,
Captain Janeway's not in any
condition to make decisions.
I'm in command.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
Good.
B'Elanna, you and Harry
get down to Engineering.
Evacuate whoever's on duty.
Then initiate the warp pulse.
Move it.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Dilithium matrix stable.
Matter/antimatter reactor
is at 80 percent of critical.
Let's keep it that way!
Warp core pressure is at
36 megapascals and rising.
When it reaches 53,
it'll trigger the shock pulse.
We should get out of here
by the time it hits 50!
Acknowledged.
Pressure at 41 megapascals
and rising.
I'm reading a micro-fracture
in the dilithium matrix.
Attempting to compensate.
Fracture sealed.
44 megapascals!
( deep rumbling)
They're heating up
the warp core.
They must be close
to initiating the shock burst.
Everybody, take cover.
47, 48, 49!
Let's move!
( dramatic theme playing )
( explosion)
Well, in spite
of Tuvok's dire predictions,
we haven't blown the ship
to pieces, have we?
No, and radiation levels are
within acceptable tolerance.
Good. Let's get in there
and see if we had any luck
dispersing
this implosion ring.
Hold it.
What?
I'm reading a massive distortion
behind the door.
I don't think
it's just behind the door.
The ring's completely
engulfed Engineering.
Can I talk to her?
I can't guarantee
she'll hear you
or be able to understand you
if she does.
Captain.
Talk... can't.
What's wrong with her?
It's possible
the spatial distortions
have damaged
her speech center.
( distorted and slow):
But without my equipment,
I can't analyze...
( normal speed ):
...her neural pathways.
Chakotay,
it didn't work.
Instead of forcing
the implosion outward,
the pulse is
drawing it in
at a faster rate.
You're saying
it made things worse?
I don't think we have
more than a few minutes.
Paris, we have to get
to the navigational array
and give Tuvok's plan a try.
I'm afraid there's no
longer time for that.
Why not?
( suspenseful theme playing )
We're not going anywhere.
Do you really think
it's possible to project
a stable holographic
force field?
We've tried
everything else.
Ready?
Here we go.
The distortion is unaffected
by the force field.
We've got to figure out a way
to generate a stable field.
B'Elanna, this ring has passed
through the shields,
crushed the hull,
twisted the ship.
We'll never get enough power
from the holo-emitters
to stop it.
What are you saying,
we're out of options?
Perhaps not. So far we have been
unsuccessful in all our attempts
to either explain or combat
this phenomenon,
and according
to my calculations,
the space
we are currently occupying
will implode in approximately
three minutes, 17 seconds.
You said there was
another option.
We do nothing.
Excuse me?
Are you suggesting we
just let it crush us?
Precisely.
( scoffs )
I can't believe
I'm hearing this from you.
I agree-- it sounds
completely illogical.
On the contrary.
When every logical
course of action is exhausted,
the option that remains
is inaction.
So we're just supposed
to sit here
and let this thing kill us?
I must point out
that at least one attempt
we made to reverse the effect--
the shock pulse--
only made our predicament worse.
If we continue desperately
improvising solutions,
our own efforts
may ultimately kill us.
On the other hand,
there is no definitive evidence
to suggest that doing nothing
will result in death.
It's...talking...to...me!
Do nothing.
Captain, please lie down.
What about the Captain?
She's dying.
We do not know that.
At the moment,
she is merely delirious.
Chakotay,
you're in charge here.
Don't you agree
we've got to keep trying?
Whatever this thing is,
B'Elanna, it's bigger
and more powerful
than we are. Maybe--
Maybe this is one bear
we can't wrestle to the ground.
Maybe like Tuvok says,
there's nothing we can do
but let it happen
and hope for the best.
( sighs)
( scoffs)
Fine.
Fine, Chakotay.
Have it your way.
Commander Chakotay.
Yes, Mr. Tuvok?
I want to thank you
for endorsing my
recommendation.
You know, Tuvok, I may not get
another chance to say this.
Sometimes I find you
arrogant and irritating,
but you're a hell of an officer.
Thank you, sir, and since
we are speaking candidly,
may I say, sir,
that I have not always been
particularly partial
to your methods either.
I suppose it must
have been tough for you
to accept my being elevated
to First Officer over you.
I have always respected
Captain Janeway's decisions.
However, I suppose
that particular decision
did put me in a position
I am unaccustomed to.
If that ever caused me to make
things more difficult for you,
I must apologize.
( faint theme playing )
KIM:
Can I ask you a question?
Fire away, Harry.
Are you afraid?
I chose this life,
and I guess I always knew
it could come to this...
but, yeah, I'm afraid.
Me, too.
I'm so worried
about Neelix.
I should be with him.
As much as he may...
annoy me at times,
Mr. Neelix is one
of the most resourceful
and resilient individuals
I know.
If anyone can survive
this calamity, he can.
TORRES:
Hi.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to contact
my spirit guide.
Why?
Who knows
what's going to happen
when that ring hits us?
We might be in
for another long journey.
I guess I could use
a little spiritual guidance
myself right now.
You mind if I join you?
I thought you'd never ask.
( sighs)
( Janeway moaning)
Captain?
I'm all right.
You were delirious.
It was...
some sort of message.
What was?
The spatial distortion.
It was...
trying to communicate with us.
( majestic theme playing )
I want a full
systems report,
and Mr. Kim, Mr. Tuvok,
I want every iota of information
that was recorded
regarding that phenomenon.
The distortion ring
is directly ahead, Captain.
It's moving away from us
at 2,000 kph.
We've got a full crew
complement, Captain.
No injuries reported.
No damage to the hull
or ship's systems.
Incredible.
You're not going
to believe this, Captain,
but 20 million gigaquads
of new information
have been input
into the ship's computer.
Where did it
come from?
My guess is, it came
from the distortion ring.
Somebody's definitely trying
to tell us something.
That's not all, Captain.
Our entire database has been
copied and downloaded
into somebody else's system.
I guess whoever
they were,
they want to know everything
they can about us, too.
Maybe it was their only way
of communicating with us.
Maybe...
they were just trying
to say "hello."
NEELIX:
Cake anyone?
Neelix, what
happened to you?
Oh, it's a long story.
I'll tell you
all about it later.
Right now, it's time
to finish your party.
Neelix, I need
a photograph of you.
What for, sweetie?
From now on, even
when we're separated,
I want to have you where
I can keep an eye on you.
Happy birthday, Kes.
( majestic theme playing )