Paris:
INERTIAL DAMPERS HAVE FAILED.
Kes:
I CAN'T GET ANY RESPONSE
FROM THE FIELD COILS.
Paris:
DID YOU VERIFY
THE CONTROL INPUTS?
STAND BY.
THE INPUTS ARE BLOCKED.
WE'VE GOT TO FLUSH
THE PLASMA INJECTORS.
OR MAYBE IT'S JUST A PHASE
SYNCHRONIZATION ADJUSTMENT.
PLASMA INJECTORS.
RIGHT.
FIELD COILS RESPONDING.
INERTIAL DAMPERS BACK ONLINE.
( chuckling )
THAT WAS NOT FAIR.
AS YOUR FLIGHT INSTRUCTOR,
IT'S MY DUTY
TO PREPARE YOU
FOR ANYTHING, FAIR OR NOT.
CLOGGING SOMEONE'S PLASMA
INJECTORS IS A DIRTY TRICK.
YES, WELL, I'M FAMOUS FOR
MY DIRTY TRICKS, YOU KNOW?
( panting )
WHAT WAS THAT?
I NEVER SAID THE SIMULATION
WAS FINISHED.
COMPUTER...
EVASIVE MANEUVERS.
( Paris and Kes laughing )
I'LL BE READY
FOR ANYTHING NEXT TIME.
OH, SOUNDS LIKE
A CHALLENGE TO ME!
( both laughing )
( bell chimes )
COME IN.
I HOPE YOU HAVE
GOOD NEWS, COMMANDER.
BASED ON THIS INVENTORY,
OUR FOOD RESERVES LOOK TO BE
DOWN TO 30 PERCENT OF CAPACITY.
GOOD NEWS AND BAD.
WE HAVE LOCATED
AN "M" CLASS PLANET.
AND IT SHOWS HIGH AMINO ACID
AND PROTEIN READINGS.
THAT SHOULD INDICATE
A HEALTHY PLANT LIFE.
WHAT'S BAD ABOUT IT?
IT'S A FULL DAY OUT OF OUR WAY.
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE ANY
CHOICE. IT'S THE FIRST CHANCE
WE'VE HAD TO REPLENISH
OUR SUPPLIES IN WEEKS.
AND OUR LONG-RANGE SENSORS
CAN'T CONFIRM ANY PLANT LIFE
ON THE SURFACE.
WHY NOT?
IT'S ONE STRANGE PLANET,
CAPTAIN.
IT'S SHROUDED.
VAPORS COVER IT
LIKE A CURTAIN.
E.M. DISTURBANCES
ALL OVER THE ATMOSPHERE.
SOME OF THESE READINGS SUGGEST A
PLANET
EARLY IN ITS EVOLUTION--
ALMOST LIKE
A PRIMEVAL EARTH.
THE PEOPLE
IN STELLAR CARTOGRAPHY
HAVE ALREADY NICKNAMED IT
"PLANET HELL."
SO IT MIGHT BE
A WILD GOOSE CHASE.
CAPTAIN, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT WE'LL FIND
WHEN WE GET TO THE SURFACE--
FLORA OR FAUNA, FRIEND OR FOE.
IF WE KNEW WE'D FIND
ANOTHER "M" CLASS
PLANET SOON, I'D...
SET A COURSE
FOR PLANET HELL, COMMANDER.
( plays Mozart concerto
in A major )
( door beeping )
THAT WAS YOU?
THAT WAS ME.
I'M IMPRESSED.
I KEEP HEARING
MY MOTHER SAY
"PRACTICE, HARRY,
PRACTICE."
SO I ATE NEELIX'S
FOOD FOR A WEEK
AND USED MY
REPLICATOR RATIONS.
PLAY SOMETHING FOR ME.
WELL, I'VE ONLY HAD IT FOR A FEW
DAYS, AND I DON'T THINK...
OH, COME ON!
PLAY SOMETHING.
JUST PRETEND
I'M NOT HERE.
( continues Mozart concerto )
PLAY SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
DIFFERENT?
SOMETHING...
NOT SO CHEERFUL.
WHY?
WHAT? YOU DON'T
TAKE REQUESTS?
SOMETHING BOTHERING YOU,
PARIS?
( sighing ):
OH, HARRY.
I'M IN TROUBLE.
WHAT'S NEW?
I THINK I'M IN LOVE.
WITH KES.
KES?
I KNOW, I KNOW!
I NEVER EVEN SAW IT COMING.
I THOUGHT WE WERE
JUST GOOD BUDDIES.
BUT THERE SHE WAS,
IN MY ARMS.
IN YOUR ARMS? PARIS...
YOU DIDN'T.
WHAT? OH! NO!
I DIDN'T.
I WOULDN'T!
SHE STUMBLED DURING
A FLIGHT SIMULATION.
I CAUGHT HER.
I HELD HER FOR AN INSTANT.
ARE YOU GOING
TO PLAY OR NOT?
A WHOLE CREW
FULL OF WOMEN
AND I HAVE TO FALL
FOR THE ONE I CAN'T HAVE.
WHY DO I DO THIS
TO MYSELF?
IF YOU ASK ME,
I SAY YOU ENJOY IT.
ENJOY IT?
ONLY THING
THAT MAKES SENSE.
YOU'VE BEEN DOING
THE SAME THING TO YOURSELF
YOUR WHOLE LIFE--
SETTING YOURSELF UP
FOR REJECTION.
YOU MUST ENJOY
PLAYING THE PART.
HEY, DON'T KNOCK IT
IF YOU HAVEN'T TRIED IT.
I JUST HAVE TO BE
MORE CAREFUL.
I CAN'T LET MYSELF
BE ALONE WITH HER.
THERE'S AN OLD
CHINESE EXPRESSION--
"STAY OUT OF HARM'S WAY."
THAT'S NOT
A CHINESE EXPRESSION.
IF IT WORKS, USE IT.
OF COURSE,
IT WOULD HELP A LITTLE
IF KES AND I WEREN'T GOING
TO BE STUCK ON THE SAME SHIP
FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES.
THAT'S A PESSIMISTIC VIEW.
I'M IN A PESSIMISTIC MOOD.
PLAY SOMETHING
PESSIMISTIC.
PRACTICE, HARRY,
PRACTICE.
( playing up-tempo,
bouncy melody )
AND THEN SUDDENLY WE FELL
INTO A SUBSPACE ANOMALY.
NONE OF THE READINGS
MADE ANY SENSE.
I DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
TERRIBLE FOR YOU.
UH, PEPPER, SWEETING?
OH. ANYWAY, IT WAS QUITE
A LEARNING EXPERIENCE.
I'M SURE LIEUTENANT PARIS
IS A FINE TEACHER.
OH, I ALMOST FORGOT,
THE PALLIANTYNE PEAS.
UH...
HMM! EVER SO LIGHTLY SPICED.
Janeway:
ANALYSIS.
HIGH LEVELS
OF TRIGEMIC VAPORS
BUT IT SHOULD STILL
SUPPORT HUMANOID LIFE.
Dr. Zimmerman:
Sick Bay to bridge.
Please turn to your emergency
medical holographic channel.
I hope you don't mind
that I've been eavesdropping.
But I have something important
to contribute.
WHAT IS IT, DOCTOR?
Of course, it wouldn't be
necessary for me
to eavesdrop if I were included
in these discussions
as a matter of operating
protocol.
DOCTOR...
You should be aware
that trigemic vapors
at the recorded levels
can cause severe humanoid
skin irritations.
COULD YOU PROVIDE SOME SORT OF
SKIN PROTECTION THAT MIGHT HELP?
I am whipping up a batch
of dermal osmotic sealant
as we speak.
Nevertheless, skin exposure
to the atmosphere
should be limited.
NOTED, DOCTOR. THANK YOU.
TELL ME, JUST HOW OFTEN
DO YOU... EAVESDROP?
I am simply
trying to monitor issues
involving the health
of the crew, Captain.
When activated,
the emergency medical program
establishes comlinks
with all key areas
of the ship, and I have...
on occasion...
I am a doctor, not a voyeur.
I am programmed to be discreet.
I AM SURE.
COMMANDER CHAKOTAY WILL DISCUSS
OPERATING PROTOCOLS WITH YOU
AT THE EARLIEST OPPORTUNITY.
IN THE MEANTIME,
NO MORE EAVESDROPPING, DOCTOR.
But, Captain, I...
THAT'S AN ORDER.
THERE'S ANOTHER PROBLEM,
CAPTAIN.
WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO TRANSPORT TO THE SURFACE
BECAUSE OF THE
E.M. DISTURBANCES
IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
THEY'LL INTERFERE
WITH OUR COMLINKS TOO.
I'LL HAVE MR. KIM
TAKE A LOOK.
LISTEN, WHY DON'T WE TAKE IN
A HOLODECK PROGRAM LATER?
A MOLIERE COMEDY--
THAT WILL CHEER YOU UP.
I THINK I'LL
JUST EAT LATER.
( chuckling nervously )
DAMN.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
VERY SIMPLE. WE JUST
WON'T SIT WITH HER.
BUT THAT'S RUDE.
NO, THAT'S SMART.
WE'LL MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
WE HAVE BRIDGE OPERATIONS
TO DISCUSS.
GENTLEMEN,
MAY I RECOMMEND
THE ALFARIAN
HAIR PASTA TODAY?
HAIR PASTA?
THAT IS JUST AN
EXPRESSION, ISN'T IT?
( laughs )
NOT AT ALL. IT'S ACTUALLY MADE
FROM THE FOLLICLES
OF THE MATURE ALFARIAN.
WE HARVEST THE HAIR
DURING SHEDDING SEASON
IN EARLY FALL.
IT'S VERY HIGH
IN PROTEIN.
WHATEVER.
WE JUST HAVE A LOT
OF BRIDGE OPERATIONS
BUSINESS TO DISCUSS.
Chakotay:
Mr. Kim, please report
to the bridge.
HAVE A NICE LUNCH.
YOU SUBCLASS GENUS.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
SITTING WITH YOUR BACKS
TO EACH OTHER
LIKE TWO STRANGERS
WAITING FOR A TRANSPORT.
THAT'S SUPPOSED
TO FOOL ME?
OH. A GUY JUST CAN'T WIN.
LOOK, THERE IS NOTHING
TO FOOL YOU ABOUT.
REALLY. I SWEAR.
LIAR.
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?
I'LL KILL YOU!
Paris:
IT'S TOO LATE!
I'M BETTING YOUR HAIR PASTA
ALREADY DID THE TRICK!
Janeway to Lieutenant Paris
and Mr. Neelix.
GO AHEAD.
YES, CAPTAIN?
Please report to my ready room
right away.
I have something important
to discuss with you.
UH, CAPTAIN, DID YOU SAY
"RIGHT AWAY"?
IF WE COULD HAVE...
That's what I said, Mr. Paris.
Janeway out.
WOULD ANYONE
CARE TO EXPLAIN?
IT MIGHT BE TOO LONG
TO GO INTO RIGHT NOW, CAPTAIN.
VERY WELL. I HAVE A MISSION
FOR THE TWO OF YOU.
WE HAVE REASON TO BELIEVE
THAT THERE ARE FOOD SOURCES
ON THIS PLANET,
BUT WE CAN'T TRANSPORT
TO THE SURFACE.
YOU'RE GOING TO TAKE
A SHUTTLE DOWN
AND DO A LITTLE SCOUTING.
ME... AND HIM?
HE'S OUR BEST PILOT,
AND YOU'RE OUR EXPERT
ON EDIBLE PLANT SPECIES
IN THIS QUADRANT.
UH, CAPTAIN,
I'M NOT ONE
TO PASS UP A MISSION,
BUT IN THIS CIRCUMSTANCE,
MAYBE ENSIGN BAYTART,
WHO IS A FINE PILOT--
THERE ARE ELECTROMAGNETIC
ANOMALIES IN THE ATMOSPHERE,
AND I WOULD RATHER HAVE YOU
AT THE HELM.
AM I... DISCERNING
A PERSONAL PROBLEM HERE,
GENTLEMEN?
FRANKLY, YES, CAPTAIN.
SOLVE IT.
YOU LEAVE AT 1400 HOURS.
WE'RE MODIFYING
THE TRANSPORTER
TO TRY AND PENETRATE
THE ATMOSPHERE.
SO FAR NO LUCK.
HOWEVER, WE HAVE BEEN RUNNING
COMPUTER SIMULATIONS
TO DETERMINE
IF THE E.M. DISTURBANCES
FOLLOW ANY SPECIFIC PATTERN.
OUR DATA ANALYSIS
SUGGESTS THAT
THERE MAY BE OCCASIONAL
ATMOSPHERIC WINDOWS
THAT WOULD ALLOW
US TO GET THROUGH.
HOW OCCASIONAL
AND HOW LONG WILL THEY LAST?
WE SHOULD SEE ONE
EVERY 30 HOURS OR SO,
BUT THEY MAY ONLY LAST
FOR A MATTER OF MINUTES.
I CAN'T BE SURE YET.
AT LEAST LONG ENOUGH FOR US
TO BEAM UP FOOD SUPPLIES.
MR. PARIS, YOU
AND MR. NEELIX WILL COLLECT
AS MANY VEGETABLES
AND FRUITS AS YOU CAN
WHILE WE WAIT FOR THIS
ATMOSPHERIC WINDOW TO OPEN.
MR. KIM, BE SURE YOUR COMPUTER
SIMULATIONS INCLUDE...
WHAT HAPPENED?
I HEARD THAT...
NOTHING HAPPENED.
THEY SAID THAT YOU
AND TOM PARIS...
KES, WE'LL TALK
WHEN I GET BACK.
I WANT TO KNOW.
NEELIX, IS IT TRUE
THAT YOU WERE FIGHTING?
WHEN I GET BACK.
SHUTTLEBAY.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
WHEN YOU HAVE A CHANCE,
COULD YOU RUN AN ANALYSIS
OF THE CYTOKINETIC
RESULTS FOR...
I DID IT DURING LUNCH.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
ARE YOU SURE?
YOU SEEM A LITTLE...
I'M FINE.
YOU KNOW, IF YOU SKIPPED
LUNCH, THE RESULT
MIGHT BE A LOWER
BLOOD SUGAR LEVEL
WHICH COULD...
I'M SORRY. IT'S
IN MY PROGRAM.
I SEE SOMETHING WRONG, I
MUST ATTEMPT TO DIAGNOSE IT.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
YOU CAN'T CURE.
NEELIX AND TOM PARIS HAD
A PHYSICAL... FIGHT.
OVER ME.
HOW DELIGHTFUL.
DELIGHTFUL?
YOU SHOULD CONSIDER IT
A HIGH COMPLIMENT.
THROUGHOUT HISTORY, MEN HAVE
FOUGHT OVER THE LOVE OF A WOMAN.
WHY, I CAN QUOTE YOU
AUTOPSY REPORTS
FROM DUELS AS FAR BACK AS 1538.
THAT'S NOT FUNNY.
IT'S NOT MEANT TO BE.
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN INTERESTED
IN AUTOPSIES.
ARE ALL TALAXIANS SO JEALOUS?
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
I'VE ONLY MET ONE.
I LOVE NEELIX.
WHY CAN'T HE
JUST ACCEPT THAT?
HIS SUSPICIONS ABOUT TOM
ARE COMPLETELY UNJUSTIFIED.
ARE THEY?
LIEUTENANT PARIS' AFFECTION
FOR YOU IS OBVIOUS.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN HE... DESIRES YOU.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
TOM AND I ENJOY
EACH OTHER'S COMPANY.
WE'RE FRIENDS.
WHENEVER YOU WALK INTO THE ROOM,
HIS RESPIRATION INCREASES,
HIS PUPILS DILATE
AND THE COLORATION OF HIS EARS
TURNS DECIDEDLY ORANGE.
UNTIL I NOTICED THE PATTERN,
I THOUGHT HE WAS SUFFERING
FROM TANZIAN FLU.
IT'S THERE FOR ANYONE
TO SEE, MAYBE NOT
IN THE SAME DIAGNOSTIC DETAIL
AS I SEE IT, YET...
ARE YOU SAYING
THAT I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE IT?
YOU'RE ONLY TWO YEARS OLD.
THERE MAY BE A FEW THINGS...
YOU DON'T KNOW
TO LOOK FOR IN A MAN.
IN TIME,
YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
ON MY HOME WORLD,
IT'S SO MUCH SIMPLER.
YOU CHOOSE A MATE FOR LIFE.
THERE IS NO DISTRUST,
NO JEALOUSLY,
NO ENVY, NO BETRAYAL.
HMM, YOUR WORLD MUST HAVE
VERY DRY LITERATURE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO HANDLE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
WHAT AM I GOING TO DO?
YOU'VE DONE NOTHING
TO PRECIPITATE
THIS STATE OF AFFAIRS.
YOU MAY NOT BE ABLE TO DO
MUCH TO RESOLVE IT, EITHER.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
YOU CAN'T CURE.
ENTRY SEQUENCE
AT TWO MINUTES. MARK.
ALL SYSTEMS NORMAL.
TRIGEMIC DENSITY
AT .041 AND RISING.
WE LOST COMMUNICATION
WITH VOYAGER 3O SECONDS AGO.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO IMPRESS
ME WITH YOUR TECHNOBABBLE.
I'M NOT TRYING
TO IMPRESS ANYONE.
I'M ENTERING IT
INTO THE FLIGHT RECORD.
LOOK, CAN I MAKE
A SUGGESTION?
YOU'RE THE COMMANDER
OF THIS MISSION.
YOU CAN MAKE ANY
SUGGESTION YOU WANT.
AND IF YOU MAKE IT AN ORDER,
I'LL EVEN HAVE TO OBEY IT.
MY SUGGESTION IS THAT WE PUT
OUR PERSONAL PROBLEMS ASIDE
UNTIL THIS MISSION
IS OVER, OKAY?
I LEFT MY PERSONAL PROBLEMS
BACK ON THE SHIP.
I CAN'T SPEAK FOR YOU.
FINE!
LET'S GET THE JOB DONE.
YOU GET US DOWN IN ONE PIECE
AND I'LL TAKE
IT FROM THERE.
ENTRY SEQUENCE
AT THREE MINUTES. MARK.
ALL SYSTEMS... STAND BY.
HAVE YOU BEEN BRIEFED
ON SHUTTLE OPERATIONS?
ENSIGN BAYTART TOOK ME
THROUGH THE BASICS.
OF COURSE, I..
I DIDN'T HAVE
THE BENEFIT OF YOUR
PERSONAL TUTELAGE.
CHECK YOUR CONSOLE.
I'M READING
A POWER-OUTPUT DECLINE
OF... 15 PERCENT.
CONFIRMED.
Computer:
Warning.
Vectored exhaust controls
malfunctioning.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
WE'RE GETTING
SOME KIND OF REACTION
IN OUR DRIVER COIL ASSEMBLY
FROM THE E.M. ANOMALIES
IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
I'M GOING TO ABORT
THE MISSION. HOLD ON.
WE'VE LOST OUR IMPULSE DRIVE!
SHUT OFF
THE DEUTERIUM FLOW.
I'M DUMPING EXCESS FUEL.
DEUTERIUM FLOW SEALED.
SETTING D.C.A. PULSE ORDER
TO NEUTRAL.
ENGAGING THRUSTERS.
CAN YOU REGAIN CONTROL?
I'M TRYING, NEELIX.
PREPARE FOR
AN EMERGENCY LANDING.
SEND OUT AN E.M.S. PULSE.
THERE'S STILL A CHANCE
VOYAGER WILL PICK IT UP.
( grunting )
CAPTAIN, WE'RE PICKING UP A
LOCATOR SIGNAL FROM THE SHUTTLE.
CAN YOU TRACK IT?
THEIR LAST VELOCITY VECTOR
INDICATES A STEEP DESCENT.
WE'VE LOST CONTACT.
BRIDGE TO TORRES.
Torres: Torres here.
B'ELANNA,
OUR SHUTTLE'S IN TROUBLE.
ANY PROGRESS ON MODIFYING
THE TRANSPORTER?
NEGATIVE.
IT'S AN EXTREMELY COMPLEX
INTERFERENCE PATTERN
AND IT KEEPS CHANGING.
BRING IN AS MUCH
HELP AS YOU NEED.
THIS IS NOW A SEARCH AND
RESCUE OPERATION.
Acknowledged.
Torres out.
KEEP ME INFORMED.
I'LL BE IN
MY READY ROOM.
I SAID...
IN ONE PIECE.
SORRY.
I DID THE BEST I COULD.
ANY BROKEN BONES?
EVERYTHING SEEMS
TO BE WORKING.
( groaning )
I'M ITCHING.
YEAH, I FEEL IT TOO.
WE'VE GOT ATMOSPHERIC
LEAKAGE IN THE HULL.
THE TRIGEMIC VAPORS
REALLY STING.
HERE.
DOC SAID
THIS WOULD HELP A LITTLE.
IF WE HAVE ATMOSPHERIC LEAKAGE,
HOW CAN WE FLY OUT OF HERE?
WE CAN'T. WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT
FOR VOYAGER TO FIND US.
WE'RE NOT EVEN SURE THEY'RE
LOOKING FOR US YET.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THE E.M.S.
PULSE GOT THROUGH.
B'ELANNA'S WORKING ON
THE TRANSPORTER,
AND ONE OF THOSE ATMOSPHERIC
WINDOWS MIGHT OPEN UP.
IN THE MEANTIME, WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO LOOK FOR
SOME KIND OF COVER.
I SAY WE STAY RIGHT HERE.
THE TRIGEMIC VAPORS
ARE GOING TO--
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO WANTS TO
GO OUT INTO THOSE VAPORS!
STAYING HERE IS OUR BEST CHANCE
OF BEING FOUND.
YOU HEARD WHAT THEY SAID.
THOSE WINDOWS ARE MAY ONLY BE
OPEN FOR A MATTER OF MINUTES.
AND WE MAY BE
WAITING HERE FOR DAYS.
EXPOSURE TO THESE VAPORS
IS TOO DANGEROUS.
WE'RE LEAVING.
GRAB YOUR GEAR.
IS THAT AN ORDER
OR A SUGGESTION?
AN ORDER!
YES, SIR.
I HOPE YOU'RE SATISFIED.
WE WERE A LOT MORE COMFORTABLE
INSIDE THE SHUTTLE.
I HAVE RED WELTS
ALL OVER MY HANDS.
YOU KNOW, IT MIGHT BE
MORE CONSTRUCTIVE
IF YOU COULD FIND US
SOMETHING SAFE TO EAT.
Neelix:
I CERTAINLY DON'T KNOW
WHY THE SHIP'S SENSORS
INDICATED THIS PLANET
MIGHT BE RICH
IN FOOD SUPPLIES.
IT SURE DOESN'T LOOK IT.
OUR EMERGENCY RATIONS
WON'T LAST FOREVER.
I'LL FIND SOMETHING FOR US.
OF COURSE,
IT MIGHT NOT MEET
YOUR PERSONAL
CULINARY STANDARDS.
OH, DON'T WORRY.
I'VE LEARNED TO
LOWER MY STANDARDS
SINCE YOU BECAME COOK.
I'M PICKING UP
SOME CAVES
ABOUT A KILOMETER
WEST OF HERE.
WHAT GOOD FORTUNE.
( door chimes )
COME IN.
HARRY.
ANY WORD YET?
WE'RE DOING
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE.
THE TRANSPORTER JUST
DOESN'T WANT TO WORK
IN THAT ATMOSPHERE.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
OH, I'M ALL RIGHT.
IT'S JUST, UH...
I WAS VERY ANGRY AT THEM
A FEW HOURS AGO.
YOU HAD EVERY RIGHT TO BE.
AND NOW THEY
MIGHT BOTH BE DEAD.
AND I'M SITTING HERE...
AND I'M FEELING GUILTY
FOR SOME REASON.
GUILTY? WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T LIKE IT.
AND IT'S THEIR FAULT
AND I CAN'T EVEN TELL THEM
HOW ANGRY I AM AT THEM
AND I MAY NEVER BE ABLE TO TELL
THEM HOW ANGRY I AM AT THEM!
SO IT DOESN'T MATTER, DOES IT?
LOOK, YOU KNOW
IF THERE WAS ANY WAY
TO LAND THAT SHUTTLE,
TOM PARIS GOT IT DOWN.
AND NO ONE HAS STRONGER
SURVIVAL SKILLS THAN NEELIX.
I'M SURE THEY'LL
BOTH BE FINE.
UNLESS THEY KILL EACH OTHER.
( laughs )
THEY'RE PROFESSIONALS.
THEY BETTER BE ALL RIGHT,
BECAUSE WHEN I SEE THEM,
I'M PERSONALLY
GOING TO TELL THEM
THAT I NEVER INTEND TO SPEAK
TO EITHER ONE OF THEM AGAIN.
Chakotay to crew,
battle stations.
THIS IS GOOD.
WE CAN LAST A WHILE IN HERE.
THAT SHOULD
DO IT.
GARNESITE.
YEAH.
THIS WILL GIVE US
A LITTLE HEAT AT LEAST.
WE BETTER CONSERVE
OUR BEACON CELLS.
SO...
( clearing throat )
WHAT IS STAR FLEET PROTOCOL
FOR SITUATIONS LIKE THIS?
OH, THERE'S
A WHOLE COURSE
AT THE ACADEMY
FULL OF ALL SORTS
OF SURVIVAL STRATEGIES.
I HOPE YOU HAD A PASSING GRADE.
B-MINUS.
THAT'S NOT VERY ENCOURAGING.
MY FATHER WAS TEACHING
THE CLASS THAT YEAR.
AND HE GAVE YOU A B-MINUS?
I GUESS HE DIDN'T
PLAY FAVORITES, HUH?
( laughs )
WHAT ABOUT TALAXIAN PROTOCOLS?
I WROTE MY OWN BOOK.
MY LIFE BEFORE VOYAGER
WAS NO BED
OF FELARAN ROSE PETALS.
( laughs )
NO, MORE LIKE A BED OF...
WHAT?
NOTHING.
YOU WERE GOING
TO SAY "JUNK" PERHAPS?
GO AHEAD. SAY IT--
JUNK.
I WAS A DEALER IN JUNK.
PERHAPS NOT WORTHY
OF A WOMAN LIKE KES,
IN YOUR OPINION.
NEELIX, I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
I NEVER EVEN--
( creaking )
TELL ME SOMETHING.
IN THAT STAR FLEET
SURVIVAL COURSE,
DID YOUR FATHER TEACH YOU
TO CHECK FOR LIFE SIGNS
BEFORE YOU SEAL YOURSELF
INSIDE A CAVE?
I CHECKED FOR LIFE SIGNS.
THERE WEREN'T ANY.
THERE ARE NOW.
HAIL THEM.
THEY DO NOT RESPOND,
CAPTAIN.
THEY'RE POWERING DOWN
THEIR WEAPONS SYSTEMS.
THE VESSEL HAS TAKEN UP
A POSITION DIRECTLY BENEATH US.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF IT,
LIEUTENANT?
THEY WOULD SEEM TO HAVE ADOPTED
A DEFENSIVE POSTURE, CAPTAIN.
I AGREE, BUT DEFENDING WHAT?
THE PLANET?
OR SOMETHING ON IT.
WHATEVER THIS LIFE-FORM IS...
ITS VITAL SIGNS
ARE AWFULLY FAINT.
IN THIS ATMOSPHERE,
IT COULD BE
DYING OF EXPOSURE.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
THEY'RE FAINT...
BUT STEADY.
I'D SAY IT'S BECOMING
MORE AND MORE EVIDENT
THAT WE CHOSE
THE WRONG CAVE.
THIS IS WHERE THE LIFE
SIGNS ARE COMING FROM.
THEY'RE EMBRYONIC
LIFE-FORMS.
THESE TWO ARE HALF FORMED,
BUT THIS ONE
ALMOST SEEMS TO BE...
THE E.M. DISTURBANCE PATTERNS
MATCH THE COMPUTER SIMULATIONS.
I'D SAY WE'LL GET A SHOT
AT AN ATMOSPHERIC WINDOW
IN ABOUT 53 MINUTES.
WHERE DOES THAT LEAVE US
WITH THE TRANSPORTER?
OUR RANGE WILL STILL BE LIMITED,
BUT THE TRANSPORTER
SHOULD WORK
AS LONG AS WE STAY
IN AN AREA
WITH REDUCED
ELECTROMAGNETIC ACTIVITY.
THE PROBLEM IS WE DON'T KNOW
WHERE OUR SHUTTLE WENT DOWN.
SO THERE'S NO WAY TO KNOW
HOW CLOSE THEY'LL BE
TO THE WINDOW WHEN
IT OPENS.
RECOMMENDATIONS?
TAKE THE SHIP THROUGH THE WINDOW
INTO THE ATMOSPHERE.
THE CLOSER YOU CAN GET US
TO THE SURFACE,
THE BETTER OUR CHANCES
FOR A SUCCESSFUL BEAM-OUT.
GET ON IT.
ARE YOU GOING TO BE ABLE
TO WARN US
BEFORE THE WINDOW
CLOSES AGAIN?
I THINK SO.
MR. KIM,
THAT'S NOT AN ANSWER
I CAN LIVE WITH.
I'LL TRY TO GET YOU
A BETTER ONE, CAPTAIN.
MR. TUVOK, WE NEED YOU TO FIND
A WAY TO GET US BY THAT SHIP.
I HAVE ANTICIPATED
YOUR REQUEST, CAPTAIN.
AM I CORRECT IN THE ASSUMPTION
THAT YOU WILL WANT TO USE
MINIMAL FORCE?
ASSUMPTION CONFIRMED.
I CANNOT
GUARANTEE SUCCESS.
MY EVALUATION
OF THEIR WEAPONS SYSTEMS
SUGGESTS A CAPACITY
EQUAL TO OUR OWN. HOWEVER...
YOU'VE COME UP WITH AN INGENIOUS
PLAN TO NEUTRALIZE THEM.
I HAVE.
IN MY ANALYSIS
OF OUR FIRST ENCOUNTER,
I HAVE DETECTED
WHAT I BELIEVE TO BE
A VULNERABILITY
IN THEIR SHIELD CONFIGURATION.
THERE APPEARS TO BE A SLIGHT
PHASE RETRACTION
WHEN AUXILIARY POWER
IS TRANSFERRED
TO THEIR AFT
WEAPONS SYSTEMS.
A CO-VARIANT PHASER PULSE
INTO THEIR AFT CONTROL SYSTEMS
MIGHT DISABLE THEIR ENTIRE
WEAPONS ARRAY.
THAT WAS
MY "INGENIOUS" PLAN, COMMANDER.
YOU ARE CORRECT.
VERY WELL. RED ALERT.
MR. KIM, SET COORDINATES.
TORRES, SPEED AT 2,000 K.P.H.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
CHAKOTAY, TAKE THE HELM.
Kim:
COORDINATES ENTERED.
ENGAGE.
THIS CREATURE'S GOING
TO HAVE THE ABILITY
TO STAND UPRIGHT.
IT HAS THE SKELETAL SYSTEM
OF A HUMANOID.
IT'S COLD-BLOODED,
HAS REPTILIAN EPIDERMIS.
ITS BRAIN
IS SIGNIFICANTLY LARGER
THAN MOST
REPTILIAN SPECIES.
I'D SAY WE'RE DEALING WITH
A SENTIENT LIFE-FORM
HERE, NEELIX.
IF THIS SPECIES IS SENTIENT
WOULDN'T THAT SUGGEST THAT
ITS PARENTS MIGHT RETURN
TO CARE FOR IT?
IT'S HARD
TO SAY.
MOST COMMON REPTILES
LAY THEIR EGGS
AND NEVER RETURN
TO PROTECT THEM.
I THINK WE'VE ESTABLISHED
WE'RE NOT DEALING
WITH A COMMON REPTILE.
TRUE.
AND IF THIS THING DOES HAVE A
MOTHER,
I'D SAY WE DON'T WANT
TO BE AROUND WHEN SHE GETS BACK.
COME ON.
WE CAN'T JUST
LEAVE IT HERE.
WE'RE NOT
LEAVING IT HERE.
ITS MOTHER LEFT IT HERE.
WE JUST HAPPENED TO WANDER IN.
BUT WE BLOCKED OFF
THE CAVE.
THE MOTHER MIGHT HAVE BEEN
TRAPPED OUTSIDE.
WE'LL LEAVE THE DOOR
OPEN FOR HER WHEN WE GO, OKAY?
LOOK, IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
WHAT IF SHE CAN SENSE
WE WERE HERE?
SHE MIGHT BE ABLE TO SMELL THAT
FAUX LIME AFTERSHAVE OF YOURS.
I'M SURE YOU REALIZE
MANY SPECIES WON'T RETURN
TO A NEST
AFTER IT'S BEEN TAMPERED WITH.
THERE'S NOT MUCH WE CAN DO
ABOUT THAT NOW, IS THERE?
WE SHOULD JUST LEAVE ALL THIS
THE WAY WE FOUND IT.
NO.
NEELIX!
THIS CREATURE
IS OUR RESPONSIBILITY.
OURS?
THE MOMENT WE CAME IN HERE
IT BECAME
OUR RESPONSIBILITY.
AND YOU EXPECT TO TAKE CARE
OF THIS THING UNTIL WHAT?
IT GRADUATES FROM HIGH SCHOOL,
COLLEGE?
AND WHAT IF MOM
DOESN'T COME BACK?
ARE YOU PLANNING TO BRING THIS
WITH US BACK ON THE SHIP?
LOOK, IF SHE DOES RETURN
AND ACCEPTS THE HATCHLING,
IT'LL SOLVE EVERYTHING.
WE JUST HAVE TO WAIT
AND SEE WHAT SHE DOES.
I DON'T KNOW HOW IT IS
IN YOUR QUADRANT,
BUT IN MINE WE DON'T ABANDON
A NEWBORN... THING.
( sighs )
FINE.
FINE, YOU'VE MADE YOUR POINT.
I OFFICIALLY DESIGNATE YOU
ITS GODFATHER.
IT STOPPED CRYING.
IT'S SHIVERING.
THAT'S NORMAL... ISN'T IT?
I MEAN, NEWBORN LIFE-FORMS
DO SHIVER,
DON'T THEY?
TO BE HONEST, I HAVEN'T BEEN
AROUND MANY NEWBORNS.
ME NEITHER.
Neelix:
AWW... LOOK AT THIS, PARIS.
IT STOPPED SHIVERING.
IT'S ASLEEP.
FORGET WHAT I SAID,
NEELIX.
YOU'RE NOT
ITS GODFATHER.
YOU'RE ITS GODMOTHER.
THE ATMOSPHERIC WINDOW
IS FORMING, CAPTAIN.
30 DEGREES OFF
THE PREDICTED COORDINATES.
HOW SOON WILL WE HAVE
MAXIMUM APERTURE, MR. KIM?
NINE MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, COMMANDER.
LET'S TRY TO DRAW SOME FIRE
FROM THEIR AFT WEAPON SYSTEMS.
BRING US WITHIN TEN KILOMETERS.
SHIELDS AT 80 PERCENT.
MINOR DAMAGE
TO OUR PORT NACELLE.
RE-ROUTING POWER
TO LATERAL THRUSTERS.
TUVOK?
SO FAR, I'M NOT DETECTING
THE SAME VULNERABILITY
IN THEIR SHIELDS THIS TIME,
CAPTAIN.
WE MAY HAVE TO RESORT
TO ADDITIONAL FORCE.
ARM PHOTONS.
Kim: READY.
PREPARE TO...
STAND BY, CAPTAIN.
I'M DETECTING
AN OPENING.
DIRECT HIT TO THEIR
AFT CONTROL SYSTEMS.
THEIR WEAPONS
ARE DISABLED.
COMMANDER, PROCEED
TO MR. KIM'S COORDINATES.
ONE-HALF IMPULSE.
Paris:
OH, COME ON. COME ON.
DOESN'T SEEM TO CARE
FOR STARFLEET RATIONS.
IF I WERE IN MY KITCHEN,
I COULD COOK YOU UP SOME
DELIGHTFUL LEOLA ROOT BROTH.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
UGH, I HOPE I NEVER
SEE ANOTHER LEOLA ROOT
AND YOU'RE CERTAINLY
NOT FEEDING
ANY OF THAT HIDEOUS
BROTH TO MY NIECE...
OR NEPHEW...
WHATEVER IT IS.
ITS HEARTBEAT
IS GETTING WEAKER.
I DON'T LIKE IT.
COME ON, KID.
YOU'VE GOT TO EAT SOMETHING.
IT SEEMS FAR MORE INTERESTED
IN MY JACKET THAN YOUR FOOD.
Paris:
NEELIX
IT'S NOT YOUR JACKET.
IT'S THE RESIDUE
OF THE TRIGEMIC VAPORS
WE WALKED THROUGH.
THINK ABOUT IT.  VOYAGER'S
SENSORS
PICKED UP HIGH LEVELS
OF PROTEINS AND AMINO ACIDS
WHICH WE ASSUMED MEANT
THIS WAS A PLANET
FILLED WITH VAST SUPPLIES
OF EDIBLE PLANT LIFE.
WE WERE CERTAINLY WRONG
ABOUT THAT.
THE RESIDUE IS A CONCENTRATION
OF PROTEINS AND AMINO ACIDS.
A PERFECT SOURCE
OF NUTRITION
FOR THE HATCHLING.
THE SOURCE WE CUT OFF
WHEN WE BLOCKED THE CAVE.
COME ON, WE'VE GOT
SOME ROCKS TO MOVE.
THE ATMOSPHERIC WINDOW IS AT
FULL APERTURE, CAPTAIN.
WE SHOULD HAVE AT LEAST
17 MINUTES
BEFORE IT STARTS TO CLOSE.
CAPTAIN, THE ALIEN VESSEL
IS IN PURSUIT.
ARE THEIR WEAPONS SYSTEMS
BACK ON LINE ALREADY?
NEGATIVE.
THEY ARE STILL DISABLED.
THEY COULDN'T BE PREPARING
TO RAM US, COULD THEY?
HOLD YOUR COURSE. WE NEED TO GET
THROUGH THAT WINDOW,
BUT PREPARE TO TAKE
EVASIVE ACTION IF NECESSARY.
UNDERSTOOD.
ALIEN VESSEL CLOSING
TO 1,000 KILOMETERS.
500.
300.
IT HAS PASSED US AND IS
PROCEEDING TOWARD THE SURFACE.
TAKE US DOWN, COMMANDER.
IT'S NOT BREATHING!
I DON'T THINK IT'S BREATHING!
COME ON, SUCK IN
SOME OF THOSE
HEARTY VAPORS.
IT'S JUST TOO WEAK.
THERE MUST BE SOMETHING IN HERE
WE CAN USE TO RESUSCITATE IT.
NEELIX, WE DID
THE BEST WE COULD.
NO!
IT'S OUR FAULT, OUR FAULT.
IF WE HADN'T COME...
HERE. CORDRAZINE.
THIS IS A STIMULANT.
YOU CAN'T PUMP IT FULL OF DRUGS
WITHOUT KNOWING
ITS BODY CHEMISTRY.
SO WE SHOULD JUST LET IT DIE?
GIVE ME THAT.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
A BABY BIRD FELL OUT OF A NEST
AND LANDED ON THE WINDOW SILL
NEXT TO MY BED.
WE HAD TO FEED IT WATER
WITH AN EYEDROPPER
TO KEEP IT ALIVE.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
FILLING THE EYEDROPPER.
CAN YOU HOLD ITS MOUTH OPEN?
DO IT AGAIN. AGAIN.
IT'S WORKING.
IT'S WORKING!
LIFE SIGNS ARE
GETTING STRONGER.
YOU DID IT!
WE DID IT.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER WOULD HAVE
THOUGHT OF THAT HYPOSPRAY IF...
THE VAPORS...
WHO CARES?
SENSORS ARE OPERATING
AS WELL AS CAN BE EXPECTED
UNDER THESE CONDITIONS.
EITHER WE'RE JUST NOT CLOSE
ENOUGH TO WHERE THEY LANDED
TO PICK UP THEIR COM SIGNALS,
OR THEY NEVER LANDED.
THEIR SHUTTLE MIGHT HAVE
BURNED UP IN THE ATMOSPHERE.
I'M NOT WILLING
TO CONCEDE THAT YET.
ANY SIGN OF THE ALIEN SHIP?
NO. CAPTAIN. WE'VE
LOST THEM.
MR. KIM, HOW MUCH LONGER
BEFORE THAT WINDOW
STARTS TO CLOSE?
NINE MINUTES, 20 SECONDS.
CHAKOTAY, EXTEND OUR
SURVEILLANCE PATTERN.
IF WE DON'T FIND THEM
IN FIVE MINUTES
WE'LL HEAD BACK
TO THE WINDOW.
AYE, CAPTAIN.
I'M SORRY.
HMM?
I FEEL I OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY.
NO, YOU DON'T.
I HAD NO RIGHT TO PUSH
THAT PASTA IN YOUR LAP.
WELL... THINK
OF IT THIS WAY:
IT SAVED ME FROM
HAVING TO EAT IT.
NOTHING PERSONAL,
BUT I JUST DON'T
HAVE AN AFFINITY
FOR HAIR IN MY FOOD.
I HAVEN'T BEEN FAIR TO YOU.
YOU KNOW, I HEAR PEOPLE TALKING
ABOUT YOU IN THE MESS HALL.
NO KIDDING.
WHAT DO THEY SAY?
OH, THAT YOU USED
TO BE A COWARD
AND COULDN'T BE TRUSTED.
IT'S TYPICAL OF KES
THAT SHE WOULD BEFRIEND
SOMEONE LIKE YOU--
SOMEONE WHO REALLY
NEEDS A FRIEND.
AND I GUESS I... JUST
GOT A LITTLE JEALOUS.
I GOT MORE THAN
A LITTLE JEALOUS.
I REALIZE NOW I WAS WRONG.
NEELIX, I TOLD YOU THE TRUTH
WHEN I SAID THAT NOTHING
HAPPENED BETWEEN ME AND KES.
I KNOW.
AND I PROMISE YOU,
NOTHING EVER WILL
BUT...
YOU WEREN'T WRONG ABOUT ME.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I...
WELL, I GUESS THE ONLY WAY
TO SAY IT IS TO SAY IT.
I AM ATTRACTED TO KES.
OH?
TO BE HONEST, IF YOU
WEREN'T AROUND,
I'D BE KNOCKING
AT HER DOOR.
BUT I RESPECT
YOU, NEELIX.
AND THAT'S THAT.
EVERYTHING YOU HEARD
THOSE GUYS SAYING ABOUT ME
WELL, IT WAS TRUE.
BUT IT'S NOT
WHO I AM ANYMORE.
AT LEAST NOT
WHO I WANT TO BE.
THIS UPSIDE-DOWN MISSION
TO THE WRONG SIDE
OF THE GALAXY
HAS GIVEN ME
A SECOND CHANCE,
AND I DON'T INTEND
TO BLOW IT.
I SEE.
WELL, IN A WAY,
I CAN'T SAY I BLAME YOU.
SHE IS VERY ATTRACTIVE.
( chuckles )
SHE'S DEVOTED TO YOU,
YOU KNOW?
WELL, I DID SAVE HER LIFE.
I'M SURE SHE'S GRATEFUL.
OH,, SHE'S A LOT MORE
THAN GRATEFUL.
SHE LOVES YOU, NEELIX.
I WOULDN'T STAND A CHANCE.
NOBODY WOULD.
THERE ARE OTHERS?
IF YOU EVER DOUBT YOURSELF,
JUST LOOK INTO HER EYES
SEE THE WAY
SHE LOOKS AT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER
DOUBT YOURSELF AGAIN.
AND AS FAR AS
I'M CONCERNED,
I'LL JUST BE HER FRIEND--
I MEAN, IF YOU DON'T MIND.
I DON'T PICK
KES' FRIENDS FOR HER.
JUST MY OWN.
( static )
VOYAGER, THIS IS LIEUTENANT
TOM PARIS AND MR. NEELIX.
DO YOU READ?
Janeway: We do, Mr. Paris.
Are you all right?
ASIDE FROM A NASTY RASH, YES.
HAVE YOU ENCOUNTERED LIFE-FORMS?
Actually, yes.
ARE THEY HOSTILE?
NO.
JUST... YOUNG.
YOUNG?
Yes, we found a nest,
and one of the creatures
hatched.
BE AWARE WE ENCOUNTERED A
HOSTILE SHIP OF UNKNOWN ORIGIN,
AND WE'RE SHOWING THAT SHIP
ON THE SURFACE
APPROXIMATELY ONE KILOMETER
FROM YOUR POSITION.
We're attempting to lock on
to you for transport. Stand by.
WE CAN'T LEAVE YET.
WHAT? WHY?
WHAT IF THE MOTHER REJECTS IT?
NEELIX, ONE
THING'S FOR SURE--
WHETHER THE MOTHER
REJECTS IT OR NOT,
SHE WILL REJECT
YOU AND ME.
WE PROMISED EACH OTHER
WE WOULDN'T ABANDON IT UNTIL...
Janeway:
Away Team, we're showing
a life-form moving
toward your position.
Prepare to transport.
CAPTAIN, THIS IS NEELIX.
ARE YOU IN A PARTICULAR
RUSH TO LEAVE?
DID YOU HEAR WHAT I JUST SAID,
MR. NEELIX?
YES, BUT WE'RE NOT QUITE
finished here yet.
FINISHED WITH WHAT? WE HAVE AN
ATMOSPHERIC WINDOW
CLOSING IN
LESS THAN SIX MINUTES.
AND ANOTHER ONE
WILL BE COMING IN HOW LONG?
DAYS. IS THERE A PROBLEM?
The problem is, Captain,
IF WE LEAVE OUR LITTLE
HATCHLING HERE
AND THE MOTHER
REJECTS IT,
it might die of exposure
before we get back.
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN
FOR ITS WELFARE...
HOW LONG CAN YOU
GIVE US, CAPTAIN?
ONE MINUTE, TEN SECONDS, MAX.
WE'LL TAKE IT!
LOCK ON TO US, VOYAGER.
IF YOU HEAR
MUFFLED SCREAMS,
CONSIDER THAT A REQUEST
FOR A BEAM-OUT.
( roaring )
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
A FAMILY REUNION.
( roaring )
VOYAGER, TWO TO BEAM OUT!
AS SOON AS YOU'RE READY.
Neelix:
KES!
WE DIDN'T KNOW IF YOU
WERE DEAD OR ALIVE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
I BECAME AN UNCLE.
AND I'M A GODMOTHER!
I'D SAY THIS IS THE SPECIAL
OCCASION I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR
TO OPEN UP THAT BOTTLE
OF POTAK COLD FOWL
I'VE BEEN SAVING.
COLD FOWL
IN A BOTTLE?
THAT'S JUST AN EXPRESSION,
ISN'T IT?
NO! IT'S ACTUALLY MADE
FROM THE GLANDULAR
SECRETIONS
OF AN ADULT DUNGHILL BIRD
FOUND ONLY ON POTAK THREE.
IT'S VERY RARE,
VERY EXQUISITE.
THERE ARE, I BELIEVE,
ONLY 27 BOTTLES
IN EXISTENCE AT THIS TIME.
IT HAS A RATHER
SMOKY FLAVOR.
UH... GOING WELL WITH
STRONG, MEATY DISHES,
BUT I PREFER IT FOR SIPPING...