Paris to the Captain.
Janeway here.
I've done an analysis of
our route through Botha space
whenever you have a minute
to check it out.
I'm on my way to Engineering.
I'll be with you
as soon as I'm done.
Aye, Captain.
Ah, Captain.
The computer told me
I'd find you
on Deck 11, Section 4B,
starboard side,
and sure enough,
here you are.
What can I do for you,
Neelix?
I assumed you'd
want to talk to me.
About?
About the Botha.
We're headed for their space,
and as I told you,
they're going to have to be
handled very carefully.
I understand, and of course
I want your counsel,
but, right now,
I'm late for a meeting.
I wouldn't put this off
too long.
We're getting closer,
you know.
Yes, I know,
and I will be with you
as soon as I can.
Sorry I'm late.
What do you have?
I think
we're about ready
to make our first
attempt, Captain.
If you're successful,
will the Doctor
be able to move freely
around the entire ship?
Not exactly.
The holo-emitters will be
set up in certain key areas--
The Bridge, Engineering.
We'll be able to transfer
him to those locations.
In the same way we can now
transfer him to the holodeck?
Exactly. But if he tries
to move into an area
where there's no emitter field,
he'll dematerialize.
KIM:
I have the holo-
projector on line.
We're ready to start.
Proceed.
I don't have much time.
TORRES:
Engineering
to Sick Bay.
Doctor, we're ready here.
I'm standing by.
Okay. Here goes.
Initiating transfer.
Here he comes.
Well, this is certainly
a brilliant feat of engineering.
What happened?
I'd guess
the imaging interface
wasn't properly stabilized.
Just a small
oversight.
No pun intended.
Very amusing.
How long will it take you
to correct
this small oversight?
Maybe a couple
of hours.
Mr. Kim, I have to assess
our navigational plan
and get ready to make contact
with an alien species.
I can't drop everything
whenever you call.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, I would like
a half an hour of your time
to review the security
protocols
before we encounter
the Botha.
Yes, Mr. Tuvok, somehow...
I will find half an hour.
DOCTOR:
Excuse me, Captain.
Would you come down here,
please?
( sighs )
Yes?
When did you last
take shore leave?
About two months ago.
Ah. How long
since you've done
something pleasurable
for recreation?
Doctor, I know I'm
a bit testy today,
but I can assure you...
How long?
( sighs )
It's... been a while.
I have a holonovel program.
It helps me unwind.
I haven't had time to
run it for a few weeks.
Well, I want you to-- Now.
Doctor, I'm really
very busy.
I've checked
Starfleet regulations.
The Chief Medical Officer
outranks the Captain
in health matters.
Now, I realize
this may be the first time
a hologram has given an order
to a Captain,
but I'm ordering you to report
to the holodeck-- Now.
Aye, sir.
And the two of you
can get busy undoing
this ridiculous blunder
of yours!
Good afternoon, milord.
Will the children be
joining us for tea?
Presently.
Lord Burleigh...
is something wrong?
Yes.
Terribly wrong.
I have fallen in love
with you, Lucie.
Milord.
Hello, Father.
We're ready for tea.
I want cucumber
sandwiches.
You'll wait your turn,
young man.
What may I serve you, milord?
Nothing. Thank you.
I see.
I want my tea in this cup,
please,
and I don't want
a cucumber sandwich.
I don't like the way
cook cuts them.
LUCILLE:
Milord, you'll
be very pleased
with the children's progress
in their studies this week.
Henry shows a real talent
for mathematics,
and Beatrice turned out
to be quite musical.
Beatrice?
Musical?
I don't know
what she means.
She's very modest
about it.
I've heard her several times
in the music room,
playing a lovely Mozart sonata,
but whenever I ask her
to play it for me, she won't.
I think her talent
should be encouraged.
Would you consider lessons?
I didn't know Beatrice
could play the piano.
( glass shatters )
I'm sorry.
It's just a cup.
Don't be a goose.
It's the flower cup--
Mother's cup.
It doesn't matter!
Mrs. Templeton!
Please take the children
to the nursery.
Yes, milord. Come.
Please stay here,
Mrs. Davenport.
Beatrice is upset.
I should be with her.
I want you here.
What's happening
in this house?
How can you not know that
Beatrice plays the piano?
Why shouldn't I go
to the fourth floor?
What's up there?
Those are questions
you must not ask.
But I am asking them.
I'm worried
about the children.
Beatrice fantasizes that
her mother is still alive.
Don't pursue this,
I beg you.
Bridge to the Captain.
Freeze program.
Janeway here.
We've been hailed
by a representative
of the Bothan government.
They'd like to talk to you.
I'll be right there.
Sorry, milord.
Duty calls.
Captain, I knew we should
have talked this morning.
Tell me what you know,
Neelix.
I've been in subspace contact
with some old friends
of mine--
Uh, nomads, collectors,
much as I used to be.
They're in a position
to gather information
during their travels.
What they've told me
doesn't sound good.
In what way?
There are lots of
rumors about ships
entering Bothan space,
never to be heard from again.
My sources on Mithren say
that they have lost
a number of vessels.
They say the Botha protect
their territory fiercely.
But we aren't aggressors.
I don't think
they are either.
They just don't want anyone
crossing their borders.
Will they negotiate?
Will they respond
to diplomacy?
It's hard to say.
There's some belief
that they don't even have
a legitimate claim
to the space--
that they're nothing more than
pernicious, odious vandals,
in which case, diplomacy
would fall on deaf ears.
TUVOK:
We're being hailed
again, Captain.
On screen.
I'm Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
Why have you entered our space
without permission?
We didn't realize
this was your space.
On what basis do you claim it?
I have no intention
of explaining myself to you.
The fact is, you're violating
our territory.
I assure you,
we mean no disrespect.
We are from another part
of the galaxy.
We're just trying
to make our way home.
We'll send a ship
to rendezvous with you.
If you meet the criteria,
we'll consider your request.
Thank you.
What are the criteria?
We'll discuss that
when we meet.
Friendly fellow.
At least they're willing
to talk.
KIM:
I wonder why he wouldn't
let us see his face.
I suspect it was
a calculated move--
An attempt to intimidate us.
Commander, you have the Bridge.
Aye, Captain.
Mr. Neelix, join me
in my ready room.
We should talk
about this meeting.
Captain, if I may...
when was the last time
you ate?
Ate?
Oh, I had some soup
last night.
Let me suggest that we conduct
our talk in the Mess Hall.
We're serving a sumptuous
repast for lunch.
Right.
Lunch it is.
Captain, you have
a nasty habit
of skipping meals,
and that can do
horrible things
to your electrolyte levels.
I know, but sometimes
I just get too busy to eat.
All you have to do
is give me a call.
I'll be there
in a trice with a tray
of foods so delectable,
you won't be able to resist.
I do think I've outdone
myself this time.
An exquisite paté made
from Seltin wood fungus.
Brine-soaked neccel strips.
Ooh.
Deviled wood throk.
Where did these come from?
Lieutenant Hargrove
asked for them.
Is something wrong?
No. Just a funny
coincidence.
Something I saw on the holodeck.
Thank you, Neelix.
This all looks delicious.
And it's bound to boost
my electrolyte levels.
( liquid pouring )
Where did you get that cup?
Why, I'm not sure.
I think I found several
of them in storage.
Unusual, isn't it?
Captain,
is everything all right?
( sighs )
It's perfectly all right,
Neelix.
I just have to remind myself
that coincidences do happen.
BURLEIGH:
I can't help myself.
I've fallen in love with you.
My mother is alive
and my father loves her,
not you.
In the course of your
experiments with the Doctor,
have you accessed any
of the holodeck programs?
No, we're bypassing
the holodecks.
Where did you get
this holo-projector?
We found several
of them in storage.
We've been reconfiguring
them one by one.
So you haven't worked directly
with any of the projectors
on the holodecks?
No.
Is there anything you've done--
Anything you can think of--
That might have caused
holographic objects
and characters
to appear outside
the holodeck?
Not that I'm aware of.
I was sure your experiments
would explain it.
Captain, there
has to be a reason
why you've had
these delusions.
And we're going to figure
out what it is.
The Doctor pointed out that
I've been under some stress.
I can't ignore that.
I think we should check out
the imaging systems
on the holodeck.
There might be
a simple malfunction.
Good idea.
TORRES: We can run diagnostic
from Engineering, but you should
activate the program first.
I'll contact you
from the holodeck.
Janeway to Engineering.
Torres here.
Have you set up the diagnostic?
We're ready, Captain.
Go ahead.
BURLEIGH:
Lucie!
Thank God you've come back.
Why are you dressed
so strangely?
It's...
a costume.
You'd look lovely in anything.
I've thought of you
constantly.
Remembered your touch...
your perfume...
your lips.
Computer,
delete character.
Torres to Janeway.
We're finished, Captain,
but we didn't find
any malfunctions.
Recalibrate and try it again.
I'm going to check
something else.
Aye, Captain.
Captain!
I'm delighted
to see you.
Do you want a snack?
No, I'm fine.
But I wanted to ask you
about lunch.
Didn't you like it?
It was delicious.
I was just trying to remember
all the dishes you made.
There was... the Seltin pâté.
Delectable.
The neccel strips.
Exquisite.
The deviled throk.
Sublime.
And the cucumber sandwiches.
Cucumber sandwiches?
Weren't there...
cucumber sandwiches?
I don't even know
what that is.
The other item on the menu
was a fried murt cake.
You ate one.
And the cup
you served my tea in?
One of these.
The ones I found
in storage.
I thought...
it had flowers on it.
Flowers?
Well, no, I don't see
any flowers.
Maybe there was another cup,
but I-I don't think so.
Would you like a cup
with flowers on it?
I'm sure I could
replicate one.
It's all right, Neelix.
You've told me
what I need to know.
DOCTOR:
I don't detect
anything so far.
No evidence of aneurysm...
subdural hematoma...
stroke.
Could it be...
stress?
Possibly.
Did you go to the holodeck,
as I ordered?
Yes.
And was that relaxing?
It was interesting.
I'm not sure how
relaxing it was.
There are other possibilities
we should consider.
I want to scan for airborne
bacteria and viruses.
We should investigate
the possibility
of an alien intruder.
And I'd like to do
a cerebro-cortical scan on you.
Oh!
Kes?
I... I don't know.
Strange.
Suddenly, I felt
cold, shivery.
Someone was walking
on your grave.
Hmm?
Just an old saying on Earth.
A way of describing
an odd feeling like that.
Hmm. How macabre.
It's a human expression,
Doctor.
I'd think
you'd have heard it.
My programmers
didn't clutter me up
with pithy Earth trivia.
They programmed me
with far more important data.
Kes, would you please get
my sub-neural scanner
from the med lab?
Yes, Doctor.
BEATRICE:
What about
my mother's grave?
There's no one inside.
The coffin is empty.
Doctor. Doctor.
Who do you see here?
I see you.
And I see you...
but I also see a little girl
from my holodeck program.
( gasps )
What happened?
I'm not sure.
The image of the little girl
suddenly rushed at me.
I saw it, too.
When I came in...
I felt as though
something hit me--
Bounced off me--
Then I saw the little girl
moving right into you.
As though you became a mirror.
You reflected her back
toward me.
I've been doing some
mental exercises with Tuvok
developing
my telepathic abilities,
but we haven't done
anything like this.
Captain, until I am able
to determine
the cause
of these hallucinations,
I'd prefer that you return
to your quarters.
Get some rest.
Vegetable bouillon.
No, cancel that.
Coffee ice cream.
( soft thuds )
Hello?
Is anyone there?
( mumbling voice )
Computer...
is there anyone
in these quarters except me?
Negative.
MAN'S VOICE:
Kath, are you there?
Who's that?
Come look at the puppies.
Mark...
( dogs barking )
I've missed you so much, Kath.
When are you coming back?
I don't think you've missed me.
Someone else
is in your thoughts now.
Isn't that true?
Isn't there someone
you're thinking of?
Computer, open the door.
Everything was fine
until you came here.
I took care of him.
He trusted me,
but when you arrived,
all that changed.
Janeway to Security.
Intruder alert.
You've done nothing
but cause trouble.
We don't want more trouble
in our lives!
( grunts )
Security
to the Captain's quarters!
Tuvok, please respond!
Captain!
Can you still see
the hallucination?
Yes. The woman
with the knife
is receding into the Captain
just like before.
Captain, listen to me!
You are in Sick Bay.
You are all right.
Captain!
( gasps )
I think Neelix can help you.
No one knows much
about the Botha,
but he has some
information.
I know he's been
doing research.
I'll check with him.
You'll probably want him
on the Bridge with you
when their ship arrives.
Good idea.
I'm not sure how Torres
and Kim are coming.
You know they're
trying to find a way
to transfer the Doctor
out of Sick Bay.
Yes.
It's not a priority...
but you might want to
stay on top of it.
Of course.
Let's see.
There was a problem with
one of the deflector shields.
You'll want to
follow up on that.
And Stellar Cartography
was hoping for a review
of their latest report.
I think Tuvok wanted to discuss
something about weapons storage.
Captain.
You've trained
your crew well.
We'll be able to do
without you for a few days.
In the meantime,
we're continuing diagnostics
on all ship's systems.
There's a reason for
what's happening to you
and we're not stopping
until we find it.
Thank you, Commander.
My patient has to rest now.
I'm sure you'll want
to get to the Bridge.
Call me if there's
anything I can do.
Just be sure to report to me
after you meet with the Botha.
Yes, ma'am.
Captain, if you'll take a seat
on one of the beds, I'd like
to do some further tests.
Kes, please
prepare the Captain
for a cerebro-cortical scan.
Certainly.
Captain, I saw
your hallucination again.
What did you see?
You were struggling
with a woman.
She had a knife.
She was trying
to hurt you.
That's right.
As I focused on you,
it was just like
with the little girl--
the image seemed
to reflect off of me
and move back into you.
Your telepathic abilities
must be increasing.
I think it's more than that.
I think something strange
is happening on this ship,
and it's not just
happening to you.
TUVOK:
I am picking up a ship
on long-range sensors,
Commander.
It is a design
we have not encountered before.
I show it
on a direct intercept course.
That must be
our welcoming party.
They're in a hurry too.
Closing fast.
They are hailing,
Commander.
On screen.
Where is your Captain?
She's not available right now.
I'm Commander Chakotay,
the First Officer.
I can speak for her.
We observe
rather strict protocols.
I'd prefer to negotiate
with the Captain.
I understand, but she's not
able to come to the Bridge now,
and in her absence,
our protocols allow me
to assume her place.
Our request is the same.
We'd like permission
to cross through your space.
We'll do it
as quickly as possible.
What kind of weapon systems
do you possess?
I'm not sure why that
information is necessary.
How do I know you aren't
a heavily armed invader,
here to attack our settlements?
I don't know
how to convince you,
but we're a peaceful people.
If you doubt us...
What happened?
I terminated
the transmission, Commander,
and made it look like
an accidental interruption.
I am concerned about some
anomalous sensor readings.
I'm getting them, too.
Residual energy displacements.
Two discrete readings--
one off the port bow,
one off starboard.
We have to consider the
possibility of cloaked ships.
Reverse course,
Mr. Paris.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
Two ships de-cloaking.
The Bothan ship
is powering up weapons.
Evasive maneuver gamma five.
Report.
Shields at 87 percent.
Minor damage on Decks 4 and 12.
They're turning back
for another strike.
Initiating evasive pattern
beta two.
Get the weapons
online.
Powering up
lateral phaser arrays.
Shields down to 83 percent.
Return fire.
A direct hit.
However, their shields
were not penetrated.
I can't stay here.
Captain, I can't allow
you to leave Sick Bay.
You're in no condition...
Sorry, Doctor.
If we're in trouble,
my place is on the Bridge.
There's something weird
going on, Commander.
I'm not reading any life signs
on the two ships
that just de-cloaked.
There's no crew?
It looks like the ships
are automated.
They're being controlled
by the Bothan ship.
Return fire, Tuvok.
We have hit their weapons array,
but not severely enough
to disable it.
Commander, the three ships
are maneuvering to surround us.
Get us out of here, Paris.
I'm trying.
The ships are powering
their weapons.
Preparing to fire.
That last volley took
our shields down to 21 percent.
We've got damage on all decks.
Reports of injuries.
All stop.
The lead ship
is hailing us, Commander.
On screen.
Your ship is damaged
and your Captain incapacitated.
I will accept
your immediate surrender.
You're not getting one.
The Captain is fine.
I don't think so.
I think the battle is over now.
Mark.
Don't you recognize
the man you love?
Mr. Paris, who do you see
on the viewscreen?
It's... my father.
I hope you've been
behaving yourself.
I see my girlfriend Libby.
Mr. Kim,
shut down visual.
I'm trying, Captain.
It won't terminate.
Mr. Tuvok, do a multiphasic
scan on those ships.
I want any evidence
of defensive weakness
and prepare the forward
photon torpedoes for launch.
Tuvok?
I do not understand
how this can be.
Don't try to understand, Tuvok.
Just accept it.
We're together again.
No.
You are not my wife.
Of course I am.
I'm T'Pel.
And there,
right in front of you,
is your lute,
the one you used to
play for me.
And look... look around you.
You're back home on Vulcan.
JANEWAY:
Tuvok?
Tuvok, answer me.
Tuvok!
Captain, I'll do it.
Running a multiphasic scan.
Torres to the Captain.
Janeway here.
We're having problems
down here.
People are becoming delusional.
JANEWAY:
It's happening here, too.
I think I know why.
There's a massive energy field
coming from those ships.
It's bioelectric, modulating
on a delta-wave frequency.
It has psionic properties,
and it's permeating the hull.
A psionic field
has a psychoactive effect.
That would explain
the hallucinations.
You can try remodulating
the shields,
but, in the meantime,
I'm going to set up a resonance
burst from the warp core.
That'll probably
block the field,
but it'll take
a while to set up.
Notify the Doctor.
If the field is bioelectric,
he might have some ideas
how to neutralize it.
Commander, give Lieutenant
Torres a hand in Engineering.
Mr. Neelix, if the crew
ever needed a morale officer,
now is the time.
See if you can help.
Aye, Captain.
Kath, do you always
have to be the Captain?
Can't you relax for a minute?
I want to talk to you.
Mr. Kim, remodulate the shields
on a rotating frequency.
Janeway to Kes.
Yes, Captain?
Can you come to the Bridge?
I think we could use you.
Right away.
Paris, are you still with me?
Sure am, Captain.
I'm running the scans
on those ships.
I'll work
on the shields.
I suggest you don't look
at the viewscreen.
It's not even tempting.
How's it going
down here?
Not good.
I can't get a response
from anybody.
It's like they're catatonic.
It's the same
all over the ship.
On my way here, I must
have seen 50 people
just sitting, staring.
A few minutes ago, there was
a momentary interruption
in the psionic field.
Were there any indications
that the alien
somehow came on board?
I'll find out.
Chakotay to Janeway.
Chakotay to the Captain.
Please respond.
Chakotay to anyone
on the Bridge.
Kim, Paris, anybody!
We may be
the last ones left.
What do we do?
I think we should take
an escape pod.
We passed an M-Class planet
yesterday.
The pod should get us there
in a week.
We can try to get help.
A week? That might
be too late.
It may be our only hope.
If we stay here,
we'll end up like the others.
No. I have to keep trying
to set up the resonance burst.
Do I have to give you
an order?
I can't believe
you're saying this.
You know we have to stay here
and try to help the others.
I want you with me.
You aren't Chakotay.
I'm the Chakotay
you want me to be.
The one who loves you.
This is what you want,
isn't it?
The secret
you've been keeping?
You want us to be together.
And we can be.
( panting )
I have to help the others.
I want you.
I've always wanted you.
( moaning )
You feel the
same way too.
Yes!
Captain, I'm getting results
from the scans.
No apparent
defensive weaknesses.
Metallurgical analysis
is inconclusive.
I can't remodulate the shields.
Try moving us out of here.
If we can get some distance
between us and those ships,
we might be able
to block the effects.
Yes, ma'am.
MAN:
This time, let's see
if you can do it
without causing
an accident.
You usually manage
to make a mess
of everything you do.
Let me say something
I've always wanted to say.
Get out of my life!
I'm just telling you
what you already know.
When the going gets tough,
you crumble.
Not anymore.
You don't really believe that
in your heart.
You believe you'll fail again
and, of course, you will.
You can't do
anything right.
You'll fail.
Why even try?
JANEWAY:
Tom?
Janeway to Engineering.
Janeway to Torres.
Are you there?
Engineering, respond.
If anyone in Engineering
can hear me, I'm on my way.
Computer, put the Bridge
controls on security lockout.
Deck 11.
Now maybe you have
time to talk to me.
You're so strong, Kath.
It's one of the things
I always loved
in you.
What's the matter?
You used to love it
when I kissed you there.
I don't know who you are--
What you are--
But I won't let you
touch me.
What about the man
on the holodeck?
You didn't seem to mind
him touching you, did you?
In fact, I think
you liked it.
Now I ask you, Kath,
is that fair to me?
I've stayed
faithful to you.
I've vowed to wait for you
no matter how long it takes.
Shouldn't you
do the same?
I haven't been unfaithful.
Oh, Kath...
Sick Bay to Engineering.
Lieutenant Torres,
please respond.
Doctor to the Mess Hall.
Mr. Neelix, are you there?
This is the Doctor
to anyone on the ship.
If you can hear me,
please reply.
Either the communications system
is malfunctioning,
or everyone on board
has succumbed
to a delusional state.
Except you and me.
It would appear
that if the psionic field
is to be blocked
and the crew restored to normal,
it's up to us.
You will have to go
to Engineering
and complete
Lieutenant Torres' efforts
to create a resonance burst.
I don't know
how to do that.
I will assist you from here.
Do you know how to do it?
I... discussed the matter
with Lieutenant Torres.
I think I understand the basic
principle behind her plan.
How hard can it be?
All right.
Go to Engineering immediately.
I'll contact you there.
( man moaning )
Tom, what happened?
A plasma leak.
Caught me in the face.
Help me.
Can you get to Sick Bay?
The Doctor is there.
Come with me.
I can't, I have
to get to Engineering.
You can't leave me
like this.
It hurts!
Tom, you can walk.
You have to get
to Sick Bay on your own.
Kes, please.
I can't.
You don't want me
to get to Engineering.
No.
I'm... I'm
hallucinating.
Kes... wait!
Come back! Don't leave me!
Come back!
Finally.
What took you so long?
Doctor, we have to set up
this resonance burst
as quickly as possible.
I've started hallucinating.
Then see if Lieutenant Torres'
last program is active.
I think I have it.
B'Elanna was writing
a program
to open
a symmetrical warp field.
All right.
You'll have to sequence
the magnetic plasma
constriction
to the following formula:
T = c sub one
over theta times p sub e.
How do I do that?
I'm not sure.
Wait a minute.
I'll see if I can access
Starfleet's
interactive database.
Sweeting!
Thank goodness I found you.
Are you all right?
Where have you been?
In the Mess Hall
trying to help
the poor souls there.
Why didn't you answer
the Doctor's hails?
I didn't hear them.
The com system must be down,
and, frankly,
I was a little busy.
Ashmore thought
I was a Kazon.
Tried to kill me
with a carving knife.
How do I know
you're really Neelix?
Who else would I be?
Kes, all I want to do
is protect you--
To keep you safe.
We have to get
away from here--
Get to my shuttle.
Doctor, have you figured out
how I can enter
that sequencing code?
It's quite simple really.
Do you know where
the command module is?
Of course.
Activate it
and select
"magnetic plasma sequencing."
You're becoming
annoying.
I-I've got it.
It's activated.
Now it's asking me
to enter the
core temperature.
Move away from that console.
DOCTOR:
Now, we need a temperature
high enough to emit
the resonance burst,
but not so high
as to irradiate
everyone on the ship.
Try three million kelvins.
( screaming )
Kes, look at him.
It hurts!
Look at him. Focus.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
The mirror, remember?
It hurts too much!
Kes, look at him.
( screaming )
What's the matter, Kes?
Can't lift your head?
Focus.
( screaming )
Stop it!
( screaming and groaning )
I'm all right now, Doctor,
and I've entered a temperature
of three million kelvin.
Then all you have to do
is activate the warp field.
All right. Here we go.
Kes to the Captain.
If you can hear me,
please report to Engineering.
What happened?
It's a long story,
but I think everything's
all right now.
Is that who's responsible
for all this?
KES:
Apparently.
He looks so harmless.
It's hard to believe
he almost destroyed us.
You're a powerful little thing.
I must say, you surprised me.
Why did you do this to us?
Because I can.
Is it just telepathy,
or is there technology involved?
Does it matter?
Oh, it matters to me,
because I don't intend
to let you continue
preying on others.
How would you
propose to stop me?
We could destroy
your technology,
or adjust
your brain wave patterns
to prevent telepathy,
and then we could turn you over
to the government of Mithren.
We could even keep you
confined in our brig
behind a force field.
I'm sure you're
very well-intentioned, Captain,
and I'd like to be able to
accommodate you...
but, you see...
I'm not really here.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We have no explanation for
the mysterious disappearance
of the telepathic alien.
We can't even be certain
that he was actually here.
He seems to have left us
with any number
of unanswered questions.
I'm surprised to see
you here, Captain.
Isn't this the day
that you're usually
in the holodeck
with your novel?
I thought after
our recent experience
that I'd take a break
from fantasy for a while.
I don't blame you.
I think... it had quite
an impact on all of us.
Do you think it's true--
that the alien
was reading our minds,
creating images
from our own experiences?
It seemed that way.
He had an uncanny ability to...
bring buried thoughts
out into the open.
Why?
Oh, it's just...
I experienced something...
I'd rather not admit.
I know.
Me too.
But in a way...
maybe he did us all a favor.
Maybe it's better to...
look those feelings in the eye
than to keep them
locked up inside.
I guess.
I'll have to think about that.
Well, I have
an early watch tomorrow,
so I'd better turn in.
Good night, Captain.
Good night, B'Elanna.
Sweet dreams.
Thanks.
You too.