( theme playing )
NARRATOR:
Ten months ago, the crew
of the Voyager was pulled
into the Delta Quadrant by an
entity known as The Caretaker.
Not enough time!
When he died, Voyager's
best chance of getting home
died with him, but he revealed
one hopeful possibility.
CARETAKER:
There is another like me.
She left hundreds of years ago,
but she's out there somewhere.
( theme playing )
TUVOK:
Open yourself
to the impressions
around you.
The thoughts, the minds
that are on this ship.
( voices murmuring )
What do you hear?
Voices.
So many voices.
I believe
you are sensing
the thoughts of various
crew members on board.
What should I do?
See if you can isolate
one of the voices.
Imagine you are
listening to a symphony
and focusing
on a single instrument.
It's working.
Try to maintain
your emotional equanimity.
You should not be concerned
with success or failure.
NEELIX:
Uh-oh. He's
taking off too much.
I told him just a few
millimeters off the top.
Way too much now.
Don't touch the sideburns.
It's Neelix!
I can hear Neelix's thoughts.
That is not unexpected.
You have an emotional
attachment to him
which may have
drawn your focus.
NEELIX:
My scalp itches.
Maybe I should tell him
about that shampoo of his.
I think he's getting a haircut.
Oh, no! He's trimming
the ear hairs.
I told him the ear hairs
were the perfect length.
Not the ear hairs!
( laughing )
If you are to succeed
in honing
your telepathic abilities,
you must learn to control
these emotional outbursts.
Outburst?
It was a giggle.
Tomorrow I
will teach you
a Vulcan mind-control
technique
that will help you
inhibit your giggles.
( sighs )
Thanks, Tuvok.
You may go.
( majestic theme playing )
You're late.
Sorry. My lesson
with Lieutenant Tuvok
went a little long today.
Today, yesterday
and the day before.
You'd think a Vulcan would be
more attuned to punctuality.
I'll try to keep
a closer eye
on the time
from now on.
So, how was
school today?
Wonderful. Tuvok helped me
with a sensory focus exercise,
we worked on
my precognitive skills
and I learned how to self-induce
a hypergogic mental state.
Sounds stimulating.
He says I'm making
excellent progress.
I had no doubt that you would
but I'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't let
these.. mind studies
interfere with your...
( high-pitched tone shrilling )
What's that?
I don't know.
( mysterious theme playing )
( shrilling stops )
( majestic theme playing )
( beeping )
Life-signs?
Apparently so.
But before I could
analyze them,
the life-signs
simply ceased.
I'm scanning the remains
on all biospectral frequencies.
It's completely inert. Dead.
Somehow, I find it
hard to believe
this rock suddenly came to life
for several seconds.
I concur. However,
dead or alive,
these are the remains
of an alien entity
we never fully
understood.
It may be prudent
to place it on
a level three biohazard
containment field.
Agreed, but first I want
to take a look at--
( shrilling )
I'm picking up life-signs.
They're sporocystian.
The caretaker was
a sporocystian life-form.
But according
to my readings,
the life-signs aren't coming
from the remains.
The remains are simply
resonating
in response to an external
energy source--
some other life-form.
Where?
Let's find out.
Janeway to bridge.
Mr. Kim, begin scans
for a sporocystian life-form.
Aye, captain. Stand by.
I've got it, captain.
A sporocystian energy burst
approximately
10 light-years distant.
But I can't get a precise fix
on its location.
The life-signs are gone.
These remains
could be responding
to the caretaker's mate.
If that's true, maybe we could
use them to track her down.
And if we can find her,
she might have
the ability
to send us home.
Torres to Janeway.
JANEWAY ( on communicator ):
Go ahead.
We've placed the remains in
a hexi-prismatic field, captain.
The next time it responds
to sporocystian energy,
the field should give us
a heading to the source.
You're using the remains
like a compass.
Exactly.
Good work.
Keep us apprised.
Janeway out.
Captain, the caretaker was
a being of considerable power.
And although his intent
was not hostile,
we were essentially
at his mercy.
I do not care to repeat
that experience.
And if we are about
to meet his mate,
you'd like it to be
on more even ground.
Precisely. I have
studied the doctor's
biochemical analysis
of the caretaker remains
and I believe it is possible to
create a sporocystian toxin--
something which might
debilitate the life-form.
Sounds like a sensible
precaution. Get on it.
( computer beeping )
I'm picking up
sporocystian energy.
Chakotyay
to engineering.
We're picking up life-signs.
Is your compass working?
TORRES ( on communicator ):
Stand by.
Activate the field.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I can't get a bearing
on the source.
Try increasing
the spatial resolution.
Spatial resolution at maximum.
The life-signs are fading,
and I still can't get
a lock
on the coordinates.
Boosting the signal gain.
We've got it, captain.
Bearing 2-7-2 mark 1-9.
Acknowledged.
Mr. Paris, set a course
and engage at maximum warp.
PARIS:
Aye, captain.
( majestic theme playing )
Captain, we're picking up
an artificial structure
on long-range sensors.
It appears to be
a space station of some kind.
Slow to impulse
and put it on screen.
That looks a lot like
the caretaker's array.
Configuration is similar.
So is the surface composition,
but it's only about
one-tenth the size.
Are there any sporocystian
life-forms on board?
No, but I am picking up over
2,000 carbon-based life-forms.
KIM:
They appear to be...
wait a second.
Confirming.
Captain.
They're Ocampa.
We're approaching the station,
captain.
All stop.
Hail them, Mr. Tuvok.
No response.
I am reading an energy surge
from the station--
possibly weapons.
Shields.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Definitely weapons.
Shields are holding.
Incoming message
from the array.
Let's hear it.
You're not wanted here.
We pose no threat to you.
I'm Captain Kathryn
Janeway of the--
You have been warned.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
They are Ocampa?
That's right. There appears
to be an entire colony.
And, according
to our sensors,
the station is
at least 300 years old.
Kes, is there
any Ocampa history
about people who
left your planet
or were captured
by aliens and taken away?
No.
The idea that
there could be Ocampa
anywhere but
on the homeworld
is something no one
ever considered.
I thought I was
the only one.
Since you're definitely
the only one on Voyager,
I want you to act
as an intermediary.
Gladly. What should I do?
The first step
is to arrange a meeting.
Let's see if we can
get that far.
Hail the array.
This is becoming tiresome,
captain.
If you force us to take
further aggressive action--
I have someone here
who wishes to speak with you.
My name is Kes.
I'm an Ocampa.
This is some kind of trick.
I assure you,
it's not a trick.
What would an Ocampa
be doing on an alien starship?
It's a long story.
But I'd like to know
what an Ocampa
is doing on
an alien space station.
That is also a long story.
Then I suggest we meet
and tell each other
our stories.
May we come aboard
your station?
No, but I am willing
to come to your ship.
( majestic theme playing )
Our readings identified
a sporocystian life-form
in this area.
We've been looking for
that life-form for months.
Why? To destroy it?
No.
On the contrary, we believe
it has the technology
that could send us home.
Captain, are you aware
of how your ship is regarded?
That when Voyager appears,
people fear destruction?
Your ship is known
as a ship of death.
What?
You've established
quite a reputation.
You killed the caretaker
declared war on the Kazon,
raided planets for their
resources.
None of that is true.
We've never attacked anyone
except in self-defense.
And we did not
kill the caretaker.
He died of natural causes.
Mr. Tanis, please
try to understand.
We only want to find
the entity we've
been looking for.
TANIS:
I want to talk to you alone.
JANEWAY:
Our sensors tell us she's
somewhere in this region.
Can you help us
find her?
Captain, I'd like to speak
to Tanis alone if I may.
Very well.
Why should I believe
any of this?
These are kind people, Tanis.
They saved my life
at great risk to themselves
when they didn't have to.
They wouldn't lie to you.
I will admit, these people
are hardly what I expected.
But more unexpected
was finding you here, Kes.
I had no idea any Ocampa
had left the homeworld
so recently.
I have about a thousand
questions to ask you.
I know. And I'm going to
try to answer them.
Is this where
you spend your time?
You mean
in this room? No.
This is where the bridge
officers usually meet.
I want to see where you live.
I want to see the place
that is special to you.
You did all this?
I had a little help,
but, yes, most of it
is my work.
Well, you've done well--
bringing something
so beautiful
into a place so sterile.
Sterile. Voyager?
Ha. Look
around you, Kes.
This is a cold
and barren place.
There are over
150 people on board.
I'd hardly
call that barren.
There are people,
but there's so little life.
Part of me weeps
to see you in this place.
You're so isolated.
Corridors, bulkheads...
all cutting you off
from the world around you.
You live on
a space station.
How is it
any different?
I assure you,
it's very different.
You're very young,
aren't you?
Two years.
Would it surprise you to know
that I'm 14 years old?
That's not possible.
( laughs )
The oldest Ocampa
only lived to be nine.
You know so little
about your own people.
There's so much for you
to learn about yourself...
about the galaxy.
Being here on this ship
is holding you back.
These people
are helping me.
I'm a member of the crew.
( laughs )
I suppose we were
like you once--
innocent, naive.
But when Suspiria brought
us here 300 years ago,
she began to teach us
how to become stronger
than we ever could have
on the homeworld.
Suspiria--is that
your caretaker?
We don't think of her
as a caretaker.
Her species is actually
called the Nacene.
Then you do know her.
Where is she?
Nearby.
But she's so different
from the entity you knew.
He was only interested
in maintaining the status quo.
He kept our people
servile and weak.
Suspiria taught us to develop
our psychokinetic skills
that had lain dormant
for so long.
We have abilities far beyond
anything you can imagine.
Like what?
( rustling )
( laughs )
TANIS:
We can enhance life.
And that's only
the beginning, Kes.
( tender theme playing )
I have to
return to the station.
We'll talk again.
Sounds like you've established
a dialogue with Tanis.
It's an excellent beginning.
Good work.
Thank you, captain.
Kes.
Is there something wrong?
Not exactly.
I'm just a little overwhelmed.
I always believed that
my people had the potential
to be more than
what they were--
that our mental abilities
could be somehow heightened,
and now I've met someone
who's realized that potential,
and I don't know whether
to be excited or frightened.
A non-emotional response
would be more useful.
But since you're
not a Vulcan,
I say a mixture
of the two emotions
would be appropriate.
It's an exciting moment, Kes,
and I'm very happy for you.
But just remember,
we know very little
about these Ocampa.
Be cautious
in your dealings with Tanis.
I will.
But I just have
a good feeling about him.
( majestic theme playing )
TANIS:
I've met with the Ocampa girl.
She has potential.
WOMAN:
I don't care about the girl.
She's yours.
Bring me the ship.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( Neelix laughs )
This is delicious!
Mr. Tanis, is it true
you're 14 years old?
Yes. That's quite common
with my people here.
Suspiria helped us
develop a technology
to extend
the Ocampa life-span
three generations ago.
My father lived
to be 20 years.
Would that technology
work for Kes?
Possibly.
Where does Suspiria live?
On another array?
Oh, nothing
so corporeal as that.
She exists as pure
sporocystian energy.
She only assumes
physical form
when we need to
communicate with her.
Does she occupy
our space-time continuum?
I don't know.
All I know is, when we
need her, she comes.
I'll take you
to the meeting place.
I'm sure all your questions
will be answered then.
You'll enjoy
meeting her, Kes,
as well as the other
Ocampa here.
I'd love to visit the station.
Visit? Why not stay with us?
Stay?
Yes. I think you could
learn a lot from us,
we from you.
We haven't been in contact
with the Ocampa homeworld
for hundreds of years.
We'd be fascinated to hear
about our distant cousins.
That sounds wonderful,
but, uh--
Kes, you certainly
don't have to decide
something this important
right now.
Give it some thought.
She's absolutely right.
There's no rush.
I appreciate that.
I am curious
about your mental abilities.
They're so much greater
than mine.
Do not underestimate
your own potential, Kes.
Your mental abilities
are rapidly maturing.
I might be able
to help you.
No offense to Mr. Tuvok,
but I am more familiar
with the Ocampa mind.
I would appreciate any insight
you could give me.
Oh, good.
Maybe later this evening.
It is a highly reactive
sporocystian toxin.
I ran a micro-cellular analysis
of the caretaker's remains,
and discovered
a critical enzyme
in his cellular structure.
The energy
in this cylinder
is formulated to break
down that enzyme.
It would result in
temporary paralysis.
Mr. Tanis says
she's harmless.
It is my hope that we
only have to use it
as a precautionary measure.
Very well. Proceed.
In your mind,
visualize your hand.
Now reach out with that hand
and grab the teacup.
Reach out with the fingers
of your mind.
Grasp it.
Do you have it?
I can feel the handle
and the texture of the metal,
but I can't move it.
Don't try to move it.
Just take a drink from it.
( mysterious theme playing )
( gasping )
See? You can do it.
I don't understand.
I didn't try to move it.
No. You just tried to drink
from it.
And what would you do
if you wanted to take a drink?
I'd reach out and pick it up.
That's right.
But you wouldn't be thinking
about picking it up.
You'd simply do it.
And that's what
you just learned.
Focus on the goal, not the task.
When you wanted the tea,
it came to you.
Uh, excuse me...
we're not finished.
I know you're tired.
But I want you to try
one more thing.
It's cold.
Wouldn't it taste better
if it were hot?
See past the liquid.
Not with your eyes,
with your mind.
What your eyes
show you
is only the surface
of reality.
Look deeper.
There is no liquid,
there is no cup.
There's only a collection
of molecules and atoms,
moving, vibrating...
I see them.
They're barely moving.
That's because they're cold.
How would you heat them up?
With...a fire.
That's right.
With the fire of your mind.
How do I do that?
Focus on the goal,
not the task.
Don't think about creating
the fire, just use it.
( mysterious theme playing )
I see it now. It's so simple.
That's right.
But that's enough for tonight.
Tomorrow, I'll take you
to the next level.
Until then, good night.
May I say something now?
Of course, Neelix.
( panting )
I'm so proud of you.
I knew you could do it.
This is a whole new
beginning for you, Kes.
I know. I know.
What if I did go?
Go?
To the Ocampa array.
If I decided to live
with Tanis and the others...
would you go with me?
I'd go anywhere with you.
( majestic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
We've arrived at what Tanis
calls the meeting place--
the region of space
where Suspiria exists.
Nothing on sensors, captain.
Captain, may I access
your communications equipment?
Of course.
( computer beeping )
I've sent out
a subspace carrier wave.
Suspiria should respond
within the next 47 hours.
I'll be in my quarters.
We'll let you know when she
makes her appearance.
That won't be necessary.
I'll know when she's here.
( majestic theme playing )
Tanis has shown me
the next level.
The pyschokinetic
manipulation of matter.
That is a large step for
someone's whose mental abilities
are still undisciplined.
Nevertheless, I am intrigued.
May I?
Please.
He showed me how to use
the fire in my mind.
( mysterious theme playing )
Fascinating.
However, I would advise caution
in exploring this ability.
Until you have mastered the...
( tense theme playing )
I have to stop the fire!
How do I stop the fire?
Tuvok. Tuvok,
can you tell me what to do?
Tuvok?
( groaning )
( screams )
( screaming )
Doctor:
Lieutenant, can you hear me?
What happened?
Your cell membranes went through
hyper-thermal induction.
The temperature
of your blood
rose by 37 degrees
in a matter of seconds.
You were in shock,
and I resuscitated you.
I'm restricting you
to light duty
for the next three days.
Try and get some rest.
That will not be
necessary, Doctor.
My Vulcan healing techniques
do not require
an extended period
of convalescence.
Vulcans make
the worst patients.
Fine, but if you're feeling
any nausea or dizziness,
I'm expecting you
to report to sick bay at once.
Of course.
Tuvok, I'm so sorry.
You are probably feeling
the emotion known as
remorse, possibly guilt.
I advise you to look
on this incident
as a learning experience.
It's not that easy.
I almost killed you.
That is correct,
but you did not.
Try to remember that.
I will see you tomorrow
at 1500 hours,
assuming you wish to
continue your training.
You still want to teach me?
If this experience
proves anything,
it is that you need
further instruction,
and I would regret not
continuing as your instructor.
Thanks, Tuvok.
( majestic theme playing )
TANIS:
How's the Vulcan?
Is he going to recover?
KES:
You heard?
In a manner of speaking.
I was aware of what happened.
He's going to be all right,
no thanks to me.
Tanis, I've been thinking--
I don't know
if I'm ready for this.
TANIS:
What's wrong?
If I can't control my abilities,
there might be another accident.
I'm afraid it isn't going
to get any easier, Kes.
You're already starting
to manifest abilities
far beyond anything
you've ever imagined.
Soon you'll be so far beyond
the other beings on this ship
that you'll look at them
as they look at...pets.
They're not pets.
They're people.
They're my friends.
And I'm sure you care
for them very much.
I'm sure
they're wonderful people.
They certainly seem
that way to me, but...
it's time that you began
to accept how different
you are from them.
The people on this ship--
they live their lives
trapped inside
their primitive skulls,
depending on flesh and bone
to tell them
what the universe is like.
They don't know what it is
to see beyond the physical.
Touch it.
This is how they
know their universe.
They touch the flower,
the nerve impulses
travel up their arm
to the brain
and in their mind, they sense
the moisture of the petals,
the texture of the leaves,
the sharpness of the thorns,
and they think they know
what it feels like,
but they don't.
Now touch it.
Reach out with
your thoughts.
Feel it...for
the very first time.
Think of nothing
but the flower.
It's the only object
in the universe.
Know it.
Know it in a way
only an Ocampa can.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Can you see it?
Yes.
It's more than seeing.
It's more than touching.
I know this flower.
You can do more.
Reach out.
Feel all the life
in this room.
( mysterious theme playing )
Yes, I can feel it.
I know them all.
They're so beautiful.
It can be more beautiful.
Bring the fire.
( panting )
( gentle theme playing )
How did it feel?
They're dead.
They're all dead.
Amazing.
You felt life.
You embraced its essence
with your mind,
and then you transformed it.
There's nothing else
like it in the universe.
I killed those plants...
just like I almost
killed Tuvok.
But I don't want
to hurt anybody.
Of course you don't.
That's not the point.
Hurt people, help them,
give life, kill.
It's all the same.
Once you see beyond
the physical,
you see the universe
as it truly is.
Now you know why you can't stay
with these people.
Why you have
to come with me.
Come back to the station.
We'll care for you.
We'll train you.
Oh, I don't know.
( laughs )
( sighs )
I still need some more time
to think about it.
Take all the time you want.
But when you meet Suspiria,
I think you'll decide
to join us.
Why?
Because Suspiria is your future.
She's part of us,
and we're a part of her.
All the Ocampa here
are connected in a way
that can't be put into words.
And if you develop
your abilities far enough,
Suspiria will invite you
to go with her to Exosia.
Exosia?
A place the humanoids
on this ship call
"A subspace layer,"
a place of pure thought,
pure energy,
a place of the mind.
Think about it, Kes.
When you're ready,
Suspiria will embrace you.
Good night.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )
Torres to bridge.
The caretaker's remains
are resonating again.
It's definitely reacting
to a sporocystian life-form.
And from what I can tell,
that life-form is right
on top of us.
Acknowledged.
Captain, there's a subspace
rupture forming directly ahead.
Yellow alert. Janeway to Tanis.
Will you please come
to the bridge?
I believe we've made contact
with Suspiria.
TANIS ( on communicator ):
I know. I'm on my way.
I think we should run
a bio-spectral analysis.
Some of these readings
are pretty strange.
And get me the sensor logs on
that subspace rupture out there.
Captain, I'm picking up some
strange readings in engineering.
Some kind of plasmatic
energy field is forming.
Janeway to Torres.
We're picking up some odd
plasmatic readings down there.
Can you confirm?
Janeway to Torres.
Security, meet me
in main engineering.
MAN ( on communicator ):
Aye, sir.
( suspenseful theme playing )
It's time to go.
Go...where?
Back to the Ocampa station.
Everyone's waiting for you, Kes.
The connection has been made.
You're part of us now.
Your future has
already begun.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Tuvok to bridge.
JANEWAY ( on communicator ):
Go ahead.
I believe the female
caretaker is here.
Commander,
you have the bridge.
TANIS:
Can't you feel
the connection?
Your people
are calling to you.
Listen to them.
Yes.
I can hear them.
All of them.
And can you hear
Suspiria?
Tuvok?
( soft crying )
Who are you?
Suspiria.
I've been looking forward
to meeting you.
Why?
Because I had the opportunity
to talk to your companion
before he died.
Yes, I know.
I can feel her presence.
She's powerful.
Turbulent.
She's upset.
( gasping )
She's angry!
Kes.
She wants to destroy the ship!
Kes, listen to me.
There's nothing to worry about.
Am I interrupting?
He told us that you were curious
and went off to explore
the galaxy.
We're explorers, too.
But your friend brought us to
this quadrant against our will,
and we haven't been able
to find a way back.
Is that why you killed him?
We didn't kill him.
You destroyed the array,
and you took his remains.
I assure you--
No!
( adult voice ):
You killed him.
And now I will kill you.
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunting )
Now you will know what frail,
small creatures you truly are.
( groaning )
( computer beeps )
What's going on?
I don't know.
It's like the entire molecular
structure of the ship
is coming apart.
Red alert.
Bridge to Janeway.
Bridge
to Janeway.
( rumbling )
We're losing hull integrity.
Increase power
to structural reinforcement.
KIM:
Aye, sir.
Forget these people.
You're beyond them.
No.
Leave her alone, Tanis.
Remember how you felt
in the airponics bay?
( gasping )
You've never felt that way
in your entire life, have you?
Get away from me.
That was only
the beginning, Kes.
I said leave her alone!
( grunts )
Neelix!
Leave him.
Leave him, Kes.
He's nothing
compared to you.
Nothing!
You have to trust.
( both gasping )
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunting )
( grunts )
Oh, Neelix.
Suspiria.
( all grunting )
( screams )
( calmer theme playing )
So, now you kill me
as you did my mate.
No. I told you
we didn't kill him.
Please try to understand.
We don't want to hurt you.
We don't want to hurt anyone.
We just want to get home.
Tuvok, release the force-field.
Captain.
Do it.
( computer beeps )
You'd show me mercy
after what I did to you?
Yes, I would.
( groaning )
Take me with you...please.
It appears she has descended
into subspace.
Can you track her position?
Negative. The rupture
has been sealed.
She is gone, captain.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
We've resumed our course
back to the Alpha Quadrant,
but the female caretaker
is still out there
with the power to send us home,
and I will use all my power
to find her
and convince her
to do just that.
I looked at the tea,
and I tried to make it boil,
but nothing happened.
Without Tanis' help,
I just can't do it.
Nevertheless,
your psychokinetic abilities
are still part of you.
They might resurface one day.
To be honest, I never want to
see that part of myself again.
To which part
are you referring?
To the part of me
that got pleasure from
destroying those plants
in the airponics bay.
To the part of me that was
tempted to go with Tanis.
I never realized I had
such dark impulses.
Without the darkness,
how would we
recognize the light?
Do not fear
your negative thoughts.
They are part of you.
They are a part of every living
being. Even Vulcans.
You?
The Vulcan heart was forged
out of barbarism and violence.
We learned to control it,
but it is still part of us.
To pretend it does not exist
is to create an opportunity
for it to escape.
Let us begin.
( majestic theme playing )
Open yourself to
the impressions around you.
The thoughts, the minds
that are on this ship.
( theme playing )