Whatever she wants us for,
it'd better be good.
Bridge.
I had you right where
I wanted you.
What are you
talking about?
I was ahead-- 19-7.
I was just lulling you
into a false sense
of security.
Sure you were.
I'll win the next
couple of points
then you'll start
to tense up.
I do not tense up.
Easy, B'Elanna.
It's only hoverball.
You wanted
to see us, Captain?
Yes, Commander.
We've picked up an intriguing
transmission.
I have a source on the signal.
A ship?
Negative. It appears
to be a beacon of some kind.
A beacon?
We are being hailed
by someone using
a Federation signal.
How could someone
be transmitting
a Federation signal
from the Delta Quadrant?
PARIS:
Maybe Starfleet found a way
to get a probe here.
Maybe they're
looking for us.
I'd like to believe that too,
but let's not jump
to conclusions.
See if you can
authenticate the signal.
The carrier
wave frequency
does correspond to standard
Starfleet security codes.
As of when?
According to
the encryption key,
this particular code
was not scheduled
for implementation until
stardate 48423.
KIM:
That's a month after
we left deep space nine.
They must be looking for us.
Your optimism may
be premature, Mr. Kim.
Sorry, Captain.
But it's also infectious.
Mr. Paris,
lay in a course
for the beacon.
Yes, ma'am.
We're approaching the beacon's
coordinates, Captain.
It's drifted inside
an ionized hydrogen cloud.
The cloud's interfering
with our sensor readings.
Can you get any information
from the beacon?
I'm afraid not.
Should I beam it aboard?
CHAKOTAY:
I'd advise against
bringing it on board
before we've gotten
a look at it.
Even if it is emitting
a Federation signal.
Agreed-- and I don't want
to fly blindly
into a hydrogen cloud either.
Mr. Tuvok, tractor the probe
into sensor range.
Aye, Captain.
Targeting scanners locked.
Initiating tractor beam.
Report!
We are taking fire
from inside the cloud.
Source?
Unknown.
Battle stations.
A Kazon raider is closing
at 158, mark 9.
Hail them, Mr. Kim.
They're not responding, Captain.
Warp three, Mr. Paris.
Get us out of here.
Aye--
Warp engines are off-line,
Captain.
Initiate evasive pattern
omega-three.
Mr. Tuvok, return fire.
Aye, Captain.
KIM:
The Kazon ship is in pursuit.
An opening is forming
in the starboard shields
72 centimeters in diameter.
See if you can
close it, Commander.
Try rotating
the shield harmonics.
TUVOK:
They are continuously matching
their weapons frequency
to our shield frequency.
How the hell
can they do that?
I don't know.
The diameter of the opening
has widened to
approximately two meters.
Set the shield harmonics
to rotate continuously.
Aye, Commander.
The opening is now four meters.
It's as if they know
our access codes.
Captain, I am picking up
a smaller vessel
emerging from
the hydrogen cloud.
It is heading directly toward
the opening in our shields.
All hands,
brace for impact.
Warning, hull breach
on deck four, cargo bay two.
Structural integrity
is at 50% and dropping.
The hull is starting to buckle.
We're losing life support
on deck four.
I'm trying to initiate
an emergency containment field.
However, the collision
has caused
a power failure on deck four.
Rerouting power to compensate.
Containment field activated.
Warning, intruder alert
in cargo bay two.
Mr. Tuvok!
Tuvok to security.
Meet me outside cargo bay two.
MALE:
Aye, sir.
TUVOK:
Drop your weapons!
It's no use.
We're not going anywhere
with that shuttle
sticking out
of our side.
It's totally destabilizing
our warp field.
Mr. Kim, did you reroute power
to transporter room two?
No, sir.
Bridge to Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
There may be intruders
in transporter room two.
I'm on my way.
Tuvok to Bridge.
JANEWAY: Go ahead.
The Kazon have beamed away,
Captain.
And they've taken one of our
transporter modules with them.
Can you lock on
to the module and beam it back?
Not at the moment.
As soon as the Kazon
dematerialized,
we lost all transporter power.
Mr. Chakotay, lock a tractor
beam on to their ship.
They're not leaving
with that module.
Aye, Captain.
KIM:
The Kazon are powering
their warp engines, Captain.
Make it fast, Commander.
Engaging tractor beam.
I've got them, Captain.
The Kazon ship
is hailing us.
Suddenly they
want to talk.
On screen.
Captain Janeway.
First Maje Culluh
of the Kazon-Nistrim.
I remember you, Culluh.
That transporter module
you just stole
is specifically designed
for our ship.
You'll never be able
to integrate it
into your systems.
I've had some help
updating our technology
since we last met.
Seska!
That's right, Captain.
As you can see,
I'm in the process
of restoring
my Cardassian physiology.
Hello, Chakotay.
I should have known
you were involved.
Yes, you should have.
Just like I knew you'd try
to stop us with a tractor beam.
You've always been
so predictable.
Captain, their deflector shields
are creating a feedback loop.
It's neutralizing
the tractor emitter.
Attempting to compensate.
SESKA:
Good-bye, Chakotay.
Lovely to see you again.
PARIS:
It's too late.
They've gone to warp.
They modified the bow
to puncture our hull.
I've never seen the Kazon
do anything like this before.
Until now, the Kazon
have never had an advisor
with Cardassian, Maquis
and Starfleet
tactical experience.
The question is,
how do we dislodge it
without losing
structural integrity?
With power down,
our containment field's
already extremely unstable.
We'll have to reroute
additional power
to the containment field
and tow their shuttle out
with one of our own.
Then we can repair the breach.
The shields and the warp drive
will have to wait.
Warp drive isn't going to do us
much good with this knife
stuck in our belly.
Get it out fast.
We don't want
the Kazon to put
too much distance
between us.
Forgive me, Captain,
but are you sure
going after the Nistrim
is the wisest
course of action?
After what they've
already done to us?
Let me make something
very clear.
The Nistrim
are in possession
of Federation technology.
That is
an unacceptable situation.
Even though
all they've stolen
is a small
computer component?
That "small component"
has the potential
to cause vast problems
in this quadrant.
You're our resident expert
on the Kazon.
What do you think
the other sects will do
when they realize
the Nistrim
have transporter
capabilities?
They'll try to get it
for themselves any way
they can. You're right.
It could alter the balance
of power among the sects.
Exactly,
and it is our duty
to do everything we can,
no matter how dangerous
to stop that from happening.
You can count on me,
Captain.
CHAKOTAY:
From the look
of these sensor readings,
Seska wants us
to come after her.
Commander?
I think Seska's leading
us into another trap.
She masterminded
a precision raid
that made us look like
first-year academy students,
but she left a warp trail
for us to follow.
After such a flawless
performance,
why would she suddenly make
that kind of mistake?
You think she wants more
than the transporter?
Are you suggesting
we don't follow her?
No, I agree with
everything you said
about preventing the spread
of our technology,
but conventional tactics aren't
going to work with Seska.
We'll need to come at her with
a few surprises of our own.
I'm open to suggestions.
Perhaps Commander Chakotay
could use his intimate
knowledge of Seska
to manipulate her
in much the same way
she manipulated us.
CULLAH:
It can move people
great distances
in the blink of an eye, Haron,
but this "transporter"
is only the beginning.
Go on.
I'm listening.
There is a ship filled
with new technology.
Devices that can
make food, water,
even weapons,
appear out of thin air.
A computer system which uses
neural tissue that can react
twice as fast as ours.
Very interesting, Culluh,
but what does all this
have to do with me?
That ship is on
its way here.
Help us, and we
can divide the spoils.
The module Seska stole
contains a quantum
resonance oscillator.
So, we modify
this coil scanner
to detect the oscillator.
Then we get close
enough to beam it back.
I'm betting Seska's
figured out a way
to shield the module
from our transporters.
We might have to
destroy it instead.
How do we do that?
We borrow a trick
from Seska's book.
Remember how we disabled
the computer core
on the Cardassian frigate
orbiting Bajor?
Seska modified
an anti-proton beam
to penetrate
its shields and hull.
Exactly.
But if I remember
correctly,
the beam
was only effective
from an extremely
close range.
How do we get near enough
to the Nistrim ship?
One thing at a time.
You're taking this all
very personally, aren't you?
Why shouldn't I?
You are not responsible
for what happened.
Oh, no? I let her
join the Maquis.
I took her
into my confidence.
I even got...
intimately involved
with her.
So you have lousy
taste in women.
Look, Chakotay,
she fooled us all.
She was my best friend--
or at least that's
what I thought.
Well, I, for one, am through
being manipulated by her.
Are you sure?
Because she's
affecting you.
That's just where
she wants you.
Don't tense up.
So now I'm getting advice
about controlling
my emotions from you.
Our sects have been
blood enemies for generations.
And yet, now you ask for my help
to defeat this Voyager.
Why not simply
do it yourselves?
I'll tell you why.
Because the Nistrim are weak
and the Relora are strong.
Your grandfather's time
has passed, Culluh.
You presided over the demise
of your own sect,
whittled away your strength--
Enough!
You may have ships
and soldiers
but I have the technology.
And I congratulate you
on the daring and cunning
of your raid.
Now, why don't
you give me
this transporter
technology,
assuming it's authentic,
and let the Relora do
what we do best.
When we have defeated
the Voyager,
we will not forget
the Nistrim's assistance.
You think I'm a fool.
I won't hand this
technology over to you.
Then perhaps we
will have to take it.
Why don't we let
the maje
go back to his ship
while we consider
his offer?
Listen to your woman,
Culluh.
( growls )
I'm picking up a gap
in the Nistrim's warp trail,
Captain.
All stop.
Let's take a look.
KIM:
Captain, I've got
some floating debris
at bearing 319.4.
On screen.
What is it?
KIM:
Not sure yet.
Magnify.
DOCTOR:
I'm detecting a residual
transporter signature.
There is no doubt that this man
and his unfortunate companion
were beamed into space.
And according
to these readings,
they were alive
at the time, Captain.
It looks like Seska's
already adapted
the transporter module
into the Kazon systems
and started
experimenting with it.
Her early trials
appear to have been
less than successful.
I'm not so sure these men
died by accident, Captain.
You see this green band
he's wearing?
It means he was the first maje
of the Kazon-Relora.
Relora?
Sworn enemies
of the Nistrim.
It's conceivable
that Seska and Culluh
used the transporter
to execute these men.
JANEWAY:
I have convened a meeting
of the senior staff
to determine how we can get
to deploy the anti-proton beam.
Where's Chakotay?
He was
in engineering
helping me modify
the coil scanner.
He said
he'd be right up.
Janeway to Chakotay.
Computer, locate
Commander Chakotay.
Commander Chakotay
is not aboard the ship.
Computer, when will we intercept
the Kazon vessel?
Approximately 30 minutes.
What I want to know,
Mr. Tuvok,
is how he was able to get
a shuttle off this ship
without either of us
knowing about it.
Apparently, he was able to
override the lock-out command.
I guess Seska's
not the only one
who knows how to compromise
our security systems.
I assure you, Captain,
it will not happen again.
See that it doesn't.
Did Chakotay leave
any clue
about what he's up to?
I have accessed
his personal logs,
but there is no reference
to his leaving Voyager.
I guess he was in too big
a hurry to leave a note.
TORRES:
The coil scanner was
right here.
He must have taken it
with him.
Then I guess it's pretty clear
he's going after Seska.
Looks like that.
You were working with him.
Did he say
anything to you?
Just that he felt
responsible for Seska,
and was determined
to stop her,
but I never thought he
would try to do this alone.
How big a head start
does he have?
Approximately three hours.
Janeway to Conn.
Paris here, Captain.
Lay in a pursuit course
for Chakotay's shuttlecraft,
maximum impulse.
Acknowledged.
And Mr. Tuvok, I want
a complete review
of all security
protocols on this ship
by 2200 hours.
Aye, Captain.
You said the Relora
would join us.
I should never
have listened to you.
I was wrong. I'm sorry.
Kazon sects do not
help one another.
Don't be so sure
about that.
What did you do to the two men
who refused your offer?
I killed them.
Yes, and by doing that,
you sent a message:
"the Kazon-Nistrim
are powerful again.
"First Maje Jal Cullah
has technology
"that no other sect
possesses.
Join with him,
or suffer the consequences."
Maybe the mistake was
to approach the Relora.
They're already strong.
But the transporter
may be enough
to convince
the Hobii to join me
and perhaps the Mostral.
Yes.
And with a few more ships,
you can defeat Voyager.
And when you have
the rest of their technology,
the other sects
will have no choice
but to fall into line.
That's why I sent
a subspace message
to the Mostral,
the Hobii,
and the Oglamar.
You did what?
I told them
about the transporter.
Asked them to help us
take Voyager.
You have gone too far.
I sent the messages
in your name.
I am the leader
of this sect.
You are only a woman.
I'm sorry, Cullah.
You will address me
as maje!
Yes... maje.
Please...
Forgive me.
So...
how did the other sects
respond to my request?
They're on their way
to join us.
I could do
what no one has done
since Jal Sankur
united the sects
to overthrow the Trabe.
Yes, Maje.
I could have hundreds of ships
and thousands of soldiers
under my command.
Yes, maje.
I could be the most
powerful Kazon in the quadrant.
Yes, maje.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Do you have a minute,
Captain?
It's about Chakotay.
That's not exactly my favorite
subject right now, Lieutenant.
Well, I thought that maybe
I could explain...
Explain what?
Why my first officer
publicly defied my authority
by commandeering a shuttle
without permission?
I know it was never
his intention to defy you.
He respects your authority.
But?
But he's a very proud man,
and he's been...
embarrassed by Seska.
What Seska did,
she did to all of us.
Frankly, I find it
more than a little
self-indulgent of Chakotay
to assume this is all
about him.
He never said it
to me directly, but...
I think he was
in love with her
and then he found out
that everything he knew
about her was a lie.
You said that he publicly
defied your authority.
Can you imagine what
it must have been like
for someone as private
as Chakotay
to be publicly humiliated
by someone he loved?
And then, as if
that weren't enough,
she came back
to taunt him
in front of the entire
bridge crew.
I'm sure it was
very painful for him
but what you're saying is
he's got a personal score
to settle.
That's only part of it.
I know Chakotay.
This is his way
of taking responsibility.
In his mind, he's trying
to protect the rest of us
from a dangerous situation
which he created.
Maybe, but that doesn't give him
the privilege
of ignoring this ship's
chain of command.
I know that.
It's just that...
Chakotay would never tell you
any of this himself.
And assuming we get him back in
one piece, you want to make sure
I take his personal feelings
into account
before I decide
how to discipline him.
I know that you are
well within your rights
to throw him
into the brig, but...
well...
Chakotay is lucky to have
such a good friend.
I'll tell you what.
Why don't we deal
with getting him back
in one piece first.
We can worry about
the discipline later.
Thank you.
Computer, when will we enter
the Kazon vessel's
scanner range?
Approximately six minutes.
Reduce power
to maneuvering thrusters
and life support
to five percent.
Cut all power to other systems.
SESKA:
The Mostral should be here
in less than 20 hours.
The Hobii in 15.
Come look at this.
Intermittent
EM readings?
I don't think so.
Computer,
initiate continuous scans
for the transporter oscillator.
Initiating scans.
Those aren't normal
fluctuations.
They're energy spikes
from maneuvering thrusters.
Probably a shuttle
running shadow maneuvers.
He knows our scanners
can't pinpoint
energy readings that low.
Who?
Maybe we can resonate
a coherent polaron pulse
off his hull.
Get a lock on him
that way.
Initiate a continuous stream
of pulses
from the lateral deflectors.
Maje?
Come on, Seska.
Where did you hide that module?
SESKA:
There you are.
Open a channel.
To whom?
Just transmit
on wide-band subspace.
He'll hear me.
Come on, find it!
SESKA:
Hello, Chakotay.
Very clever maneuvering
but I'm not about to let you
ruin all my hard work.
Deploy a spread
of photonic charges
centered on coordinates
124 by 217--
20% nominal yield.
That won't be enough.
We want that shuttle
intact.
Got you.
Computer, power
the anti-proton generator.
Generator ready.
Target a concentrated beam
to these coordinates.
Beam targeted.
Initiate!
The generator is off-line.
Great.
Computer, launch the automated
message beacon.
Beacon launched.
Now take the inertial dampers
off-line.
He's lost control
of the shuttle.
We have him.
Lock the towing emitter
onto his vessel
and bring him into
the main hangar.
Culluh calling Seska.
This is Seska.
He's not here.
He must have
transported aboard.
Find him!
CHAKOTAY:
I'm right here.
Activate the message beacon.
Lovely to see you again.
TUVOK:
Captain, I'm detecting
a Federation beacon
at bearing 059, mark 72.
This one's definitely ours--
Starfleet issue.
All stop.
The beacon is transmitting
an automated message.
It is from Commander Chakotay.
On screen.
...to Voyager.
If this signal
has been activated,
it means that I have destroyed
the Nistrim's
transporter capabilities.
Captain, I apologize for acting
without authorization,
but I ask you
not to put the ship or crew
in further jeopardy
by attempting to rescue me.
It's unlikely
that I'm still alive.
Chakotay to Voyager.
If this signal
has been activated...
You can go.
I see the Nistrim
take orders from you now.
Let's just say I'm in a position
of some influence,
which is fortunate for you.
Culluh wanted to
execute you immediately,
but I convinced him that
you'd be a valuable prisoner
and that I should be the one
to interrogate you.
Lucky me.
Would you like a drink?
The Kazon word for this
is "enemy's blood."
it's not exactly fine cognac,
but I've developed
a taste for it
try some.
No, thanks.
You know, I've got
to hand it to you.
I thought all these months
answering to Janeway
would have made you soft,
but all you needed was
a little slap in the face
to get that Maquis heart
of yours beating again.
Here's to old times.
I have no interest
in reminiscing with you.
I destroyed
the transporter module.
The game's over.
What do I need with a single
transporter module
when I've got your shuttle
and all its technology
sitting in our hanger?
I think you'll find
that technology useless.
I wiped the computer core
before I transported.
I should have anticipated that.
So if you're going
to have me killed, just do it.
You're still the noble one,
aren't you?
Ready to die for your shipmates.
You know, Chakotay,
I may not have
the transporter anymore,
but I've got
something better:
You.
Maybe that's all
I really wanted.
I've missed you.
You can't possibly believe
that you and I
could still--
Don't flatter yourself.
It was never that good.
You might have been
an interesting
diversion now and then,
but I've always been
less interested in you
than in the information
you could provide me with.
First, you gave me your
Maquis secrets
and now I want
Voyager's command codes.
If you think I'm going
to give you those codes,
you don't know me
as well as you think you do.
Maybe not, but
for old time's sake
I'll let you in
on a little secret.
There are half a dozen ships
from other Kazon sects
on their way
here right now.
They're joining us
to help take Voyager.
Why are you telling me this?
I'm not a monster.
I still care about Torres
and some of the others.
I don't want to see
anybody get hurt.
I never did.
I'm touched.
These Kazon aren't as
reasonable as you and I.
I'm going to have to
use all my influence
to make sure they
don't kill you all.
But you've got to give me
something to work with.
Voyager's not coming.
I left them explicit
instructions not to follow me.
So you can stop worrying
about people getting hurt.
They'll come.
They'd never leave
their first officer
in the hands of the Kazon.
You may not give me
the command codes,
but when Culluh gets through
with you, you'll wish you had.
The message appears
to be authentic, Captain.
We've got
to go get him.
Commander Chakotay has
expressly requested
that we not attempt
to do so.
We don't have
to honor that request.
Captain?
If a rescue
attempt forces us
to engage the Kazon,
there is always
a possibility
that more
of our technology
will fall
into their hands.
Kim to the Captain.
I'm picking up several vessels
converging
on the Nistrim's location.
My gut tells me
we should
go after Chakotay...
but my better judgment...
tells me we should honor
his request.
I would never want you to
ignore your judgment, Captain
but let me ask you this:
In your judgment
how would the loss
of our first officer
affect this crew?
What would it do to
the morale on this ship?
Maybe this is
an instance
when your gut is giving
you better advice.
Janeway to Conn.
Paris here.
Resume a course for
Chakotay's shuttle.
Aye, Captain.
CULLUH:
I'm losing patience,
Federation.
Just tell him what
he needs to know.
She's quite a
woman, isn't she?
Does she rub
your shoulders
and tell you you're
the most exciting man
she's ever known?
That's what she
used to do for me.
What's the matter?
Didn't she tell you
about us?
Stop playing games
and give me the command codes.
Flattery, devotion, sex...
I always thought she had
a lot to offer a man.
You talk too much,
Federation,
but you're not telling me
what I need to know.
You're wrong, Culluh.
I'm telling you exactly
what you need to know.
She's using you.
I'm the one
who's using her.
You've done an
even better job
on him than
you did on me.
You talk to me,
not to her.
Then what's
she doing here?
Watching you work?!
She used to like
to watch me work too.
I don't believe a word
you're saying,
so you can stop trying
to distract me now
and start answering
questions.
You know one thing
I especially liked?
The little mole on her stomach.
I've guess you've seen it.
I'm through wasting
my strength on you.
( distorted )
Now give me the command codes.
I'll give you something better.
What?
Firsthand information.
Go ahead.
When Seska's through with you...
( laughing )
...she's going to kill you.
He's delirious.
He doesn't know
what he's saying.
Give him some time.
I'll be back in one hour.
For his sake, he'd better
be more cooperative.
Very clever ploy, Chakotay,
but you know
I'm not a killer.
( groaning )
If I were, you'd
have been dead
a long time ago.
I have located
the Nistrim vessel
on long-range sensors.
Distance: .4 light years.
However, they are not alone.
There are now at least
six other Kazon ships
in the immediate vicinity.
I didn't think Culluh
had that many ships.
They must belong
to enemy sects.
That may be so,
but the ships have not
powered their weapons systems.
What do you make of it,
Neelix?
It's certainly
unusual for rival
Kazon sects
to congregate peacefully.
Is it possible the Nistrim
have formed
an alliance with
other sects?
I've never known the Kazon to do
anything like that before.
If the Nistrim have added
six ships to their force,
it would be tactically unwise
to engage them.
Then we'll just
have to find a way
of getting Chakotay out of there
without picking a fight.
We can transport him out.
We would have to slow down once
within transporter range,
giving the Kazon
ample time to open fire.
Not necessarily.
We could beam him out
at warp speed
without even slowing down.
The Kazon would never
be able to catch us.
KIM:
That's difficult enough
when both ships
are traveling at warp.
The Kazon ship's not moving.
I can compensate for that.
How?
By synchronizing
the transporter's
annular confinement beam
to the warp core frequency.
KIM:
Maybe, but at a relative speed
of two billion kilometers
per second,
it's pretty tough
to get a lock on somebody.
Ensign Kim is correct.
We would risk scrambling
his transporter signal
and killing him.
It would be a direct violation
of Starfleet safety protocols.
Do you have
a better idea?
Trust me, Captain.
I can do it.
How can you be
so sure?
Because
I've done it before.
When you are a Maquis,
you don't always have
the luxury
of following protocols.
CULLAH:
Ah!
Jal Surat of the Mostral.
May I present
Jal Loran of the Hobii
and Jal Valek of
the Oglamar?
We've met before...
in battle.
Please, Jal Surat, sit down.
Today is a day
Kazon children
will remember for generations.
Today is the day we put aside
our differences,
and join forces
to defeat Voyager.
Today is the day
that marks the end
of the supremacy
of the Relora and the Ogla,
because, after today, we will
have the Federation technology
and the other sects
will run when they see us.
That's a fine speech, Culluh,
but what makes you think
Voyager won't use
this technology to defeat us?
Because I have
Voyager's command codes.
I have heard what you did
to the Relora maje
and his companion.
Very impressive.
But before I make
an enemy of these Federations,
I want proof that you have
their command codes.
May I present
Commander Chakotay,
Voyager's first officer.
60 seconds to transporter range,
Captain.
Bridge to Torres.
Have you located Chakotay?
I'm reading Kazon life signs,
but still no Chakotay.
Captain, I must reminder you
that we have no direct evidence
the commander is still alive,
or if he is,
that he's still
aboard that ship.
I'm not conceding that yet.
Can you give me
anything, B'Elanna?
I'm picking up some kind
of localized dampening field.
It's blocking
our targeting scanners.
Maybe Seska's found a way
to hide Chakotay from us.
You may be right.
I've got to re-initialize
the targeting scanners
to match the relative phase
of the dampening field.
I've found him, Captain.
He's still alive.
Can you get him
out of there?
The dampening field
is disrupting
our transporter signal.
I can't get a lock on him.
Red alert.
Mr. Paris,
take us out of warp.
( alarm blaring )
It's Voyager.
Well, Culluh?
What are you waiting for?
Use the command codes
to disable them.
Bridge, this is
First Maje Culluh.
Lock weapons onto
the Federation ship and fire.
Mr. Paris, evasive
pattern delta-four.
Mr. Tuvok, return fire.
Firing phasers.
Bridge to Torres,
can you transport Chakotay?
I'm matching
the pattern buffer frequency
to the Kazon dampening field.
Make it fast.
I've got a lock.
Initiating transport.
Do you have him, B'Elanna?
I had him for a second
but they've re-modulated
the dampening field.
Can you compensate?
I'm trying,
but I need more time.
We'll try to hold them off,
but we don't have long.
Mr. Tuvok, phasers
to maximum.
Let's give them
a little distraction.
Why are you allowing them
to continue firing?
It's taking longer
than I thought
to interface
with their systems.
You must order your ships
to provide cover.
I hope you know
what you're doing.
The other Kazon vessels
have opened fire.
Mr. Paris, evasive
pattern omega-two.
Aye, Captain.
Bridge to Torres.
You're going to have
to hurry it up down there.
We can't hold them off
much longer.
I'm doing the best I can.
We're losing patience, Culluh.
Where are you going?
To the Bridge.
I might have better luck
interfacing with Voyager's
systems from there.
I'll go with you.
You'll stay right here.
Aft shields down
to 23%, Captain.
Bridge to Torres.
Can you transport
Chakotay out or not?
They've put the dampening field
on some kind
of randomly fluctuating
modulation.
It'll take me at least an hour
to match the phase variances.
Shield's at 16%.
Captain, we
must retreat.
Lieutenant,
just how localized
is that dampening field?
A little more than two
meters in diameter.
Just enough to isolate
Chakotay. Why?
I think I've got an idea.
I don't think you ever
had those command codes.
I think you're a liar.
What does it matter?
If we work together,
we don't need
the command codes to beat them.
You're right.
We can beat them,
but we're going to
do it without you.
We're taking your ship.
TUVOK:
Please stay
where you are.
You will find that
our transporters
have rendered
your weapons useless.
I will make you very sorry
for this, Culluh.
Here are the terms,
gentlemen.
The safe return of our first
officer and shuttlecraft
in exchange
for your freedom.
I presume you will find that
an acceptable arrangement.
JANEWAY:
Now that Commander Chakotay
has made a full recovery,
I'm faced
with the difficult task
of responding to his failure
to follow procedure.
Just tell me one thing.
What were you thinking?
About keeping our technology
out of Kazon hands.
I thought if I did it on my own,
I could keep the rest
of the crew out of danger.
That may be
a very noble sentiment,
but it wasn't
your decision to make.
Oh, Chakotay...
we've spent the last ten months
together on this ship.
I thought we had
an understanding.
Why did you choose
to ignore procedure?
Seska was my problem--
a problem I felt
it was my duty to solve.
So you had a...
personal score to settle.
I thought I was doing
the right thing.
Really?
Tell me this--
how do you expect me
to keep order
when the first officer
takes it upon himself
to run off like some cowboy
because he decides
it's a good idea?
What you did
was commendable.
The way you did it was not.
You set a terrible example,
and on a personal level
you've made my job
more difficult.
If that's so, I regret it.
I'm putting you on report,
in case that means
anything anymore.
It means something
to me, Captain.
It means
I've let you down
and for that,
I'm truly sorry.
TUVOK:
Bridge to Ready Room.
Go ahead, Mr. Tuvok.
I think you
and Commander Chakotay
should come in here.
On our way.
I have located an automated
message beacon, Captain.
Another one?
It is a message
to Commander Chakotay
from Seska.
Would you like Mr. Kim
to put it through
to your office?
No, I think I've spent
enough time alone with Seska.
Very well.
Put it on screen.
Hello, Chakotay.
Congratulations
on your victory.
I look forward
to our next meeting.
Oh, and there's something
you should know.
While you were unconscious, I
took the liberty of extracting
a sample of your DNA.
I impregnated myself with it.
So, I guess more
congratulations are in order.
You're going to be a father.