We need this
completely filled.
We don't have time
to haggle over price.
Understood.
Captain.
Janeway to Voy...
GUARD:
Get up!
MALE:
Get away from her!
Commander--
any word on
that tellerium?
Not yet. How bad is it?
The antimatter
reaction rate
is down to 12%.
If it drops below nine the
plasma injectors will lock up
and we'll never be able to
reinitialize the nacelles.
Options?
If we're going to reduce our
power demands even further,
we're going to have to drop
the shields.
I don't want
to be defenseless
this close
to a hostile planet.
All other systems
are already off-line.
Life support
is at minimal.
You asked for options?
That's our last one.
All right, power
down the shields.
That helped.
It's only a matter of time.
There's nothing more we can do
without the tellerium.
Neelix to Voyager.
Yes, Neelix.
The rest of the away team
is gone, Commander.
They've been taken
by the Mokra.
What do you want me to do?
Did you get the tellerium?
Yes, I have it.
Then we need you here.
Prepare to beam to engineering.
Rerouting emergency power
to transporter room two.
And...
energizing.
Chakotay to away team:
Captain, can you hear me?
Unlock the control conduit.
CHAKOTAY:
Tuvok, Torres?
Please respond.
Keep an eye on the float rate.
Yes, sir.
CREWMAN:
Rate's holding steady.
KIM:
The reaction rate
is stabilized at 13%.
Up to 15... 18.
It worked then?
We're all right?
Maybe.
Once the rate is normal
we'll try getting
the warp drive back on-line.
Then we'll see
if there was any damage.
Begin rerouting power back
to all key systems.
What happened down there?
I don't know, exactly.
I went in the shop,
completed the trade,
then I heard weapons fire
on the street.
By the time I got out there,
they were gone.
Are you sure
it was the Mokra?
I spoke to witnesses
on the street.
They said it was quite a fight.
Any idea how the Mokra knew
you were down there?
Someone must have told them
we were coming.
The Mokra have informants
everywhere.
Could your contact
be one of them?
I don't think I would have
made it back here
with the tellerium
if he had been.
Besides, he's involved
with the Alsaurian
resistance movement.
He would never help the Mokra.
They've probably got
the resistance movement
under surveillance.
KIM:
Commander--
I think we're ready
to give the engines a try.
I'm opening
the plasma injectors.
Warp engines are back on-line.
All systems normal.
Good work, Mr. Kim.
Mr. Neelix,
you're with me.
I think it's time
we contact the Mokra.
Mr. Paris, set a new course.
Bring us out from behind
the moon and establish
the standard orbit
around the planet-- slowly.
We don't want
to look aggressive.
Yes, sir.
What kind of response should we
expect when they see us?
The Mokra are paranoid
and hostile.
They have little use
for diplomacy.
I wouldn't be surprised
if they started shooting
at us immediately.
We'll be in full view
of the planet in a few seconds.
Their orbital sensor net
has picked us up.
They're scanning the ship.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
I am Third Magistrate Augris
of the Mokra order.
Commander Chakotay of
the Federation Starship Voyager.
May I assume
you're seeking permission
to conduct business with us?
No.
Some of my crew members
have already been
to the surface.
We've lost contact with them.
I see.
You must have been unaware
of our regulations.
I'll transfer
a complete copy
for future reference.
I have reason to believe
they're being detained.
Detained?
That's possible.
I'll look into it for you.
I'll contact
you shortly.
Thank you.
He's not like any Mokra
I've ever met.
I can't believe he'll
really help us.
If there's any chance
for a diplomatic solution,
we have to pursue it.
In the meantime I want
continuous scans of the surface.
Standard search pattern.
I advise caution.
There's a control circuit there.
I can see it.
If only we knew
that Neelix made it,
back to the ship
with the tellerium.
Then at least this
would be worth it.
I regret I have no such
reassurance to offer you.
We don't even know what happened
to the captain.
She might have been killed
out there on the street.
That is possible.
It is also possible
that she has safely
retuned to Voyager.
We have insufficient
evidence to dismiss
either conclusion.
I guess that's
the Vulcan way
of telling me
to hope for the best.
( someone humming )
( groaning )
Look who's awake.
Just rest.
You must be thirsty.
Maybe hungry?
For a little something?
Where am I?
Oh, it hasn't been that long.
I wish I had some... there.
This will do.
Drink.
Thank you.
I'll fix you some soup.
Now, just lie down.
You're very kind, but I--
It's all right.
You're safe now.
I really can't--
Shh-shh.
Don't worry.
Everything's all right now.
My little girl is home.
I'm very grateful
for everything
you've done for me.
But you know there's nothing
I wouldn't do
for my sweet Ralkana.
My name is Kathryn Janeway.
"Kathryn"?
That's an unusual name.
Very pretty.
I like it.
I am a starship captain.
It is very important
that I contact my ship.
Wonderful.
Captain Kathryn...
of a glorious starship.
Then what happens?
Go on.
I'm listening.
I love your stories.
It's not a story.
It's a request.
May I use your
communications equipment?
Communications...
Uh, we're not supposed
to have any of that.
The Mokra don't allow it.
They can't have control
of everything.
Surely there's someone
who has an illegal transmitter.
I know what you'd like--
some talsa root soup.
Can you tell me what happened
to the people I was with
on the street?
You really should be
more careful out there.
Those Mokra will pick
a fight for no reason.
I don't want you
getting hurt... again.
But I saw the way you handled
that ugly one.
I couldn't have
done any better.
I was so proud
of you, Ralkana.
My two friends--
did the Mokra take them?
I'm afraid so.
Where would they
have been taken?
A detention center?
The prison.
All right.
How do I get there?
Soup.
I'm forgetting the soup.
I appreciate your hospitality
but I can't stay here.
I've got to get to that prison.
You're right,
the time has come.
Now that we're together again,
we can't wait another day.
My beautiful...
and brave girl.
The Mokra won't stand
a chance against us.
You're very kind to offer
but I didn't mean
we'd be going
together.
You must eat and rest
to get your strength back.
We'll leave soon enough.
We don't want
to keep her waiting
any longer
than we have to.
Keep who waiting?
She must miss you
so terribly.
It's hard to bear,
thinking of her alone
in that dark cell.
It's been difficult
for all of us
but don't worry,
we'll get her out.
You'll see
your mother again.
Our world has come
under attack before.
You can understand
our concern
at finding strangers
who arrive secretly
from a hidden ship.
I assure you, we have
no hostile intentions.
I believe you,
but some of
my colleagues
are cautious about
dealing with...
disreputable ships.
What does that mean?
It seems you've been making
more enemies than friends
since you arrived from the...
alpha quadrant, is it?
Some think even that story
is a lie.
But not you.
Of course not.
I am here to help.
Then I'd like to talk
to my crew members.
I'm afraid that
will be difficult
in the current climate
of mistrust.
Perhaps if you
could tell us
more about what
brought you here--
who you've been
dealing with.
I'll consider that
after I talk
to my crew members.
You're not
making it very easy
for me to help you.
Let me see
what I can arrange.
It may take some time.
Commander.
Talk to your contacts again.
I want an alternative
to sitting here
waiting for him
to get back to us.
Your question is based
on a faulty assumption.
I cannot answer it.
You can't deny being in contact
with the resistance.
I deny that we
are intending
to supply them
with weapons.
These lies are useless.
We know you're
helping the subversives.
I want names.
I have none
to give you.
We told you already,
we don't know
anything about
the resistance!
I've heard that many times
from many people.
Take him.
TUVOK:
Lieutenant, stop!
That will not
help either of us.
He's right.
SOLDIER: Open up!
FEMALE: No!
SOLDIER: Break it down!
( yelling continues )
( door opening )
I see soldiers out there. What's
happening?
They're everywhere,
searching the whole area.
I don't want to cause
trouble for you.
I'll go soon as it's dark.
You've always been
a troublemaker
ever since you could walk.
I've never seen
such a willful child.
But that's what
I love most about you,
your spirit.
Now, don't worry.
When they come through here,
we'll be gone already.
Now, your mother will want
some of her things.
Ah... a pretty dress
to wear.
They're only looking for me.
You don't have to get more
involved than you already are.
Why, if my precious
girl is involved
then I'm involved too.
Do you remember this?
She always used to wear it
on special occasions.
I think today
would count... as one.
You know what I think
she would like even more?
Is to see you wearing it.
I couldn't possibly take it.
Be careful. Be careful.
This won't heal if you
move around too much.
If you want to help
tell me about
that prison.
What kind of security
do they have?
Are there force fields,
detection grids,
physical barriers?
Yes, all of it.
What about guards?
Lots of guards.
The Mokra make
a big show of it--
always bragging about
how no one
has ever escaped.
Listen to me...
I can't bring you
to prison with me.
It's too dangerous.
I'm not afraid.
And that could get
both of us killed.
You have to stay here.
If I stay here I can't
bring the letters.
Letters...
to the prison?
Letters.
Don't you remember how we used
to write to her together?
Here they are.
I still write them--
every week since
she's been gone...
I've always known
that one day
I'd be able to...
to give them to her.
I've never forgotten.
These are all
to your wife?
How long has it been?
My last letter...
My last letter is not...
it's not here.
Oh, I wrote it three days ago,
but it's... it's not...
I can't let her think
I've stopped writing--
that I gave up hope only,
only days before...
Huh, I'll write it again.
My hand...
My hand shakes sometimes.
You write it so it looks nice.
I'm very sorry, I have to go
before the soldiers come
the last one...
the last one was about...
My memory isn't very good.
No, I remember.
I went walking in the morning.
It was... it was very cold.
Tell her I wore my sweater.
She worries about
that sort of... thing.
And... and, uh...
And I, uh, and I what?
And I saw that they had
torn down that old building
where you and the other children
used to... to play.
And, uh... what else?
Tell her that it rained
for two and half days.
I don't know
if she can see the sky...
where they're keeping her.
And... there was more.
There was something
about a friend... I, uh...
I...can't I remember?
I wanted to tell her!
It's all right.
She'll understand.
Yes, yes, you're right.
She will.
Please let me come with you.
I'm sorry.
That's not possible.
SOLDIER:
Check this one here!
( banging )
Is there another way out?
( soldiers yelling,
banging continues )
There.
SOLDIER:
Open the door!
Open the door, now!
SOLDIER:
Break it down!
( tapping )
This is a waste of time.
We don't need him anyway.
I need him.
If he's a member
of the resistance
he may be able to help me
contact my ship.
Monster!
He's the one.
He took your mother.
We have to...
they want a fight.
Don't give them one.
( shouting and scuffling )
MALE:
I've done nothing.
Please, please!
AUGRIS:
You look like
a helpful citizen.
So tell me, you might have
seen some strangers
who were in the
market place earlier today.
MALE:
No, sir. No, sir!
I've seen no one.
Please.
AUGRIS:
You!
I'm looking for someone,
a woman.
I haven't seen
any woman.
There are two
right over here.
You see them,
don't you?
MALE:
Yes.
Maybe we should
discuss this elsewhere.
( whispers )
Caylem!
Good morning.
(laughter)
I seem to have lost my hat.
It's about this... this big.
Have you seen my hat?
Run along, old man.
Without my hat?
There you go.
( laughter )
The... it's
all right now.
They've gone.
( footsteps and guards'
chattering receding )
( distant screaming )
NEELIX:
The prison is in the northeast
corner of the city.
My sources tell me
it's surrounded
by metaphasic shields.
Can we find a way
to beam through them?
The Mokra aren't familiar
with transporter technology.
There is a periodic
fluctuation
in the shields energy pattern.
I'm working on a way
to take advantage of it.
There's only one
problem with that.
If the Mokra detect us
breaking through
their shields,
we'll be surrounded
by soldiers in seconds.
If we could
beam in close enough
to where the away team
is being held
we might be able
to get in and out of there
before the Mokra
had a chance to react.
We can't locate
the away team from here.
The detention level
is subterranean
and the rock is too dense
for our sensors to penetrate.
You'll have to look for them
after you beam into the prison.
Too dangerous.
We can't risk beaming in.
We'll have to find another way
that the Mokra won't detect.
Sounds like a challenge
for you, Mr. Kim.
MALE:
You'd be welcomed to use our
transmitter if we still had one.
The Mokra confiscated
it this morning.
Then I'll have to find
my crew members myself.
I know two of them were
arrested, what about Neelix?
He stayed
inside with me,
then got transported
up to your ship.
Good. What can you
tell me about the prison?
I know about the prison.
We need all the information
we can get.
I have to reach my crew.
Don't you think there are people
in there I'd like to get out?
Any sane person would
tell you it's impossible.
Spoken like a coward.
I've heard about you old man,
you're the coward!
Enough.
What are you doing
with this lunatic?
Has he been telling you
stories of his brave deeds?
They're just fantasies.
Taking him along on this
rescue mission of yours
is suicide.
He's already saved me
from the Mokra once.
And he saved you from
those soldiers today.
All right,
stay with him.
Go off to the prison,
get yourself killed.
I don't have to get killed
if you will tell me
what you know.
There are access tunnels
on the north side.
They'll get you in a little
closer, but they're guarded.
Then I'll need weapons.
They're not free.
I don't have
anything to trade.
That's worth
some weapons.
I can't.
Yes, you can...
if it'll help
to bring her back to us.
Thank you.
I can have someone meet you
on the street
in three hours
to make the trade.
He'll be wearing
a blue vest.
Watch for him.
We will. Thank you.
I'd wish you luck,
but what you'll need
is a miracle.
He's more than
three hours late.
We have to consider
the possibility
that he's been arrested.
You mustn't believe what
he told you about me.
I don't believe it.
You're not a coward.
I had to keep
my little girl safe.
It was just too dangerous
to get involved.
Can you understand?
Your mother wouldn't listen.
She wanted to fight.
She was always... so passionate
about what she believed in.
She didn't care about the risk.
You were proud of her.
I didn't want to lose her.
I didn't want you to grow up
without a mother.
I tried so hard
to change her mind
and finally she changed mine.
She convinced me
to go with her.
I said I would meet her...
by the river.
She was leading a raid
against a Mokra supply center.
I said I would meet her...
but I didn't... I couldn't.
I was too afraid.
She was still waiting for me
when they arrested her.
I could never tell
you about this.
I knew you would
hate me.
I couldn't bear that.
Please, Ralkana.
If you can ever forgive me...
What is it?
A blue vest.
Then it's time to go.
What happened?
He was wearing
military boots,
like the Mokra. It was a trap.
A trap?
And you saw it?
My clever girl.
We'll be all right.
We have each other.
That's all we'll need.
It's not that simple.
We can't just walk into
the prison without weapons.
Maybe we'll have to try
a different strategy.
( grunting )
We don't have to ask
your friend any more questions
if you give us the answers.
I told you I don't...
( panting )
I'm sorry.
I guess I...
I always assumed
that Vulcans
didn't feel pain
like the rest of us.
That you were able
to block it out somehow
until I heard...
was that you I heard?
Vulcans...
are capable of suppressing...
certain levels
of physical pain.
Beyond that,
we must simply
endure the experience.
How can you say that
so calmly?
You must feel some anger
at what they did to you.
Some desire
to fight back.
Under the circumstances,
physical resistance
is ineffective.
We are... fighting back
by refusing to give them
any information.
GUARD:
Get down there!
Three more hours.
GUARD 2:
There's nothing going
on around here.
Wake me if the lieutenant
shows up, will you?
( footsteps approaching )
You girls aren't supposed
to come down here anymore.
Do you want me to leave?
I didn't say that.
Then I won't.
If my lieutenant saw
you here I'd be in trouble.
Nobody will
see us back here.
It's dark...
private.
I like this strategy.
Ready to go?
No... you're not coming with me.
Of course I am.
We settled this.
You told that man, Darod,
how I saved you
from the Mokra!
You did save me.
Now I'm returning
the favor.
( force field deactivating
and reactivating )
I promise I'll try
to find your wife.
Wait!
Ralkana!
No!
I've been studying
their orbital sensor net.
It surrounds
the entire planet.
This is the most sophisticated
system I've ever seen.
It monitors everything we do,
there's no way
of disabling it from orbit.
So much for a surprise attack.
We may still be able
to surprise them
even if they do
see us coming.
We can modify
the main deflector
to send out send out
dozens of radion beams
which should penetrate
the prison shields.
One of them will carry
our transporter signal.
But the sensor net won't be
able to distinguish which one
so the Mokra won't know
the exact location
we're beaming to.
Then they won't know where to
concentrate their defenses.
That's the best head start
I can give you.
Then it'll have to do.
How long will it take
to modify the deflector?
I can do it right now.
Chakotay to Paris:
Is the rescue team ready?
Standing by.
Prepare for transport.
Deflector ready,
Commander.
Initiate the radion beams.
Sending out
the first volley.
It's working. They're getting
through the shields.
Begin the transport.
Transporter room two,
synchronize
your confinement beams to--
that came from the surface.
Maximum shields.
Damage report.
Shields at 90%.
That was a precision hit right
to the source of the beams.
Main deflector is now offline.
We're being hailed
from the surface.
On screen.
Your attempt
to penetrate our defenses
is a hostile act
against the Mokra order.
There are now 85
phased-ion cannons
targeted at the your ship.
If you don't withdraw from
Mokra space in two minutes,
we will open fire.
( alarm blaring )
Commander.
Give me some good news,
Mr. Kim.
There's a disruption in
the shields around the prison.
That qualifies.
Good work.
I wish I could
take credit for it,
but it's coming from
inside the prison.
Can we get through?
Yes, but the Mokra will
detect our transport.
Sounds like they have
other things
to worry about right now.
That disruption might
not be accidental.
Someone in there might
be trying to get out.
That's big assumption.
Even if our people
didn't cause the problem
you know they'd take
advantage of it.
This is our best chance
to find them.
In about 30 seconds,
the Mokra are going
to open fire.
I don't know how
long we'll be able
to wait for you.
Understood.
JANEWAY:
Darod.
I'm looking
for my people.
They're back this way.
I'll show you.
( footsteps approaching )
Don't move.
( sighs )
There you are.
What are you doing here?
I will do everything
in my power
to protect
my only child.
( sighs )
There's a phased-ion charge
coming at us from the planet.
Full power to the shields.
KIM:
Shields at 60%.
Minor damage on deck 14.
They're firing again.
Modulate the shield frequencies.
Try to throw off their sensors.
No effect.
Direct hit to the port nacelle.
Redirect all warp power
to the shields.
Two more coming in.
Captain.
( sighs )
We've got to get you
back to the ship.
You're hurt.
Ralkana,
the other cells are this way.
We must find your mother.
Follow this passageway
until it dead-ends.
Then you'll see
a smaller passageway.
Captain, what are you doing?
There's one more person
I have to find.
Guards!
After all that time
I spent looking for you,
all I had to do was wait here.
Shields down to 23%.
We've got to get out of
their weapons range.
Scan one more time
for the away team.
There's no sign of them.
Prepare to break orbit.
Wait-- set a course bearing
2-1-9 mark 4-7.
Where are you
taking us, Mr. Kim?
There's a large
electrical storm
over the northern
magnetic pole.
It's giving our
sensors some trouble.
It should do
the same for theirs.
A blind spot?
Exactly.
If we maintain our position
directly above the storm,
their sensor net
may not be able
to keep an accurate lock
on our position.
How long do you think
this will work?
The storm's already
dissipating.
A few more minutes.
I'll take every second
I can get.
I must say
I'm impressed, Caylem.
You never made it
this far before.
Every so often
he goes on one
of his missions...
to rescue his wife.
She's been dead
for 12 years.
Lies.
Lies... lies!
Sometimes... he gets all
the way up to the front gate.
We send him on his way
and allow him
to serve as a reminder
of just how futile it is
to challenge us.
I thought you'd learn
that lesson
when you lost your daughter.
She made it as far
as the tunnels
before she was shot.
No!
So much tragedy
for one man to bear.
And now your foolishness
has condemned
another innocent woman.
Take the others back
for questioning.
I'll interrogate
this one myself.
No!
I won't let you
hurt her!
( groaning )
Caylem!
Ralkala...
He said
you'd been shot.
He was lying
to you, father.
I'm all right.
And your mother?
She's fine.
She was so happy
to get your letters.
She wanted me
to tell you something.
She forgives you.
We both do.
My sweet girl.
Captain.
I'm coming.
No one will forget
what he did here today.
I'll make sure of that.
Chakotay to
Transporter Room Two.
Do we have them?
JANEWAY:
We're all back, Commander.
Take us out of here.
Gladly.
Lieutenant,
you heard her.
KIM:
The warp drive is
functioning normally
and we'll have
the main deflector back on-line
tomorrow.
Yes, thank you,
Mr. Kim.
Captain, are
you all right?
I'm fine.