It's extraordinary.
I must remind you
( device chittering )
that it is also
a potential security risk.
It's losing power.
I'd like to move it
to Engineering
to see if I can repair it
before it drains completely.
I suggest we allow
the power to drain.
We should take
the opportunity
to examine it
while it is idle.
Then we can decide
whether it is wise
to repair it.
Captain, this thing
has a completely
unfamiliar power source.
Once it stops working,
it's very possible I'll never be
able to get it going again,
and we'll have lost
an opportunity
to study a new technology.
This is a ship
of exploration, Mr. Tuvok.
TORRES:
The power's surging.
If we can't find
a way to stabilize it,
we're going to lose it.
What about an interface
with an EPS power conduit?
Well, the
energy signatures
are incompatible,
but it might
buy us some time.
( whirring )
Okay, let's give it
a try.
TORRES: Two-second burst,
five percent maximum output.
On my mark.
Now.
We're losing it.
Maybe we're overloading
its systems.
Let's try
a longer burst
at lower power.
Got it.
Five seconds
at three percent.
On your mark.
Now.
I think
it's working.
EPS flow
is holding steady.
EM field leakage
is minimal.
We'll have to watch the pressure
at the connector.
Let's try to keep it below
eighty-five percent.
Flux capacitance is spiking
intermittently,
but I don't think
that's the problem.
Let's reinforce the power
conduit coupling,
just to be on
the safe side.
( dramatic
theme music playing )
TORRES: It's suffered
a lot of damage,
but I think
the EPS charge
will keep it running
for at least 18 hours.
It's not a cyborg.
It's completely robotic.
No organ components
of any kind.
This looks like some kind
of programming center.
But I'm not detecting
any pathways
for transmitting
information.
It's got arms, legs.
We saw it move its head.
It's clearly designed
to perform motor functions.
So where do those
commands come from?
Maybe it needs to interface
with an
outside source.
Speaking of sources,
this energy module
seems to be what powers
the entire mechanism.
It isn't designed
to run on EPS energy.
It runs on some kind
of super-conducting plasma.
( gasps )
If we keep charging it,
we may end up destroying it.
( high-pitched tone )
( babbling )
It's trying
to communicate.
We don't know that. It may just
be some kind of recording.
Pralor! Pralor!
Pralor! Pralor! Pralor!
What are you
trying to say?
What's "Pralor"?
If you can hear me,
try to move...
Try to move your arm.
B'Elanna, we don't even know
if it can see you,
much less understand
a word you're saying.
We've got to figure out
a way to fix it.
We've been trying for hours.
We need a break.
The EPS charge should
hold till morning.
You go ahead.
I could use some time
alone to think.
If you're staying,
I'm staying.
Get some rest, Harry.
You may think you're tougher
than everybody else,
B'Elanna Torres,
but I can go without sleep
just as long as you can.
Don't make me laugh,
Starfleet.
And don't make me
pull rank on you either.
If you insist.
But let me know if you
come up with anything...
Lieutenant.
TORRES: Chief Engineer's Log:
Supplemental.
I've tried 13 different methods
of reinitializing
the robot's power source
and I'm still having no luck.
So I've decided
to go to the mess hall
to recharge my own
declining energy reserves.
Neelix, I need
another pot of coffee.
Even though breakfast
isn't officially served
for another
hour and a half,
I'd be happy to pour you
a glass of traggle nectar.
I will even fix you
my special Jibalian
seven-spice omelet.
Just coffee.
I'm sorry, B'Elanna,
but two pots of Lauris blend
is the absolute limit.
You're cutting me off?
Oh, I guess
you're right.
It was starting to
taste almost palatable.
Still no idea how to revive
our mechanized guest?
All I've been
able to do
is postpone
the inevitable.
The constant
power depletion
is like a
bleeding artery,
and haven't got
a tourniquet.
I remember
when I was trying
to perfect the recipe
for my Jibalian omelet.
I tried everything--
a little more spith basil,
a little less prishic--
but I couldn't get it right.
Finally, I fell asleep
from exhaustion.
Right there
at the counter.
And then, in a dream,
it came to me.
I was using six spices,
but the omelet needed seven.
Let me guess.
Leola root.
Nimian sea salt,
actually.
Salt?
Yes, salt--
the most common spice
in the galaxy.
But I was too tired,
so I couldn't see it.
That is...
a very interesting
story, Neelix.
Now, how about
some more coffee?
To bed.
I said to bed...
I'm going.
( sighs )
( hollow knocking )
Anybody home?
What's that?
You think I should
go to bed too?
Well...
I guess I'm outnumbered.
Computer, activate Emergency
Medical Holographic program.
Please
state the nature.
If there has been a change
in the official dress code,
I certainly wish someone
would have informed me.
This is what I sleep in.
I didn't have
time to change.
I see.
May I assume your haste
is an indication
that you have a medical
problem of some kind?
An engineering
problem actually,
but I thought you
might have some insight.
Hm. I should remind you
I'm a doctor...
Not an engineer. Right.
But this isn't a typical
engineering problem.
I've been working on
trying to repair a robot.
Ah, yes.
The mechanical man.
Kes told me about it.
Fascinating.
He's about to die.
Die?
Die. Stop functioning.
Whatever.
Unless I can figure out a way to
sustain his main energy source.
What kind of energy source
are we talking about?
Well, it's some type
of chromo-dynamic module
powered by
a tri-polymer plasma.
But the plasma
is contaminated.
It's decaying.
Hm. Like diseased blood.
Right. It can't retain enough
energy to keep the module
running.
Have you considered
a transfusion?
You mean replacing
the plasma itself?
Well, that was one
of my first ideas.
But where do I get my hands
on a polymer plasma
composed of elements
I didn't even know existed
24 hours ago?
Aren't Voyager's engines
powered by warp plasma?
Well, it's a very
different substance.
It's too highly charged.
It would burn out
the robot's systems in seconds.
It would be like
trying to give a Bolian
a blood transfusion
from a Vulcan.
Which ordinarily
would kill
the unfortunate Bolian.
But there
have been instances
when artificial blood
was unavailable,
and existing blood cells
were genetically altered
for interspecies
transfusions.
It's a good idea,
but warp plasma radiates
at too high a frequency
to alter electro-chemically.
Unless...
Go on...
I could modify a series
of anodyne relays,
attach them directly
to the robot's power module.
They could act
as a sort of regulator
to make
the warp plasma compatible
with the robot's
energy matrix!
That's exactly
what I was going to suggest.
That's the last
of the relays.
The plasma injector
is sealed.
This is your show,
Lieutenant.
Whenever
you're ready.
Activating the relays.
All right, Harry,
start the infusion.
20% nominal flow.
Initiating plasma flow.
Energy levels
are up 14%.
The relays
are holding.
Harry, give it
a little more juice.
Got it.
I'm taking it
to 30 percent.
35 percent.
Wait. The energy levels
are rising too fast.
We're going
to burn out its systems.
But it needs more plasma.
What about increasing the
capacitance of the relays?
Let's give it a try.
It's stabilizing.
Hold the flow
right there
and see what happens.
The plasma's
circulating.
The programming center
is activated.
I think we may have done it.
( gasps )
MALE COMPUTER VOICE:
Please identify yourself.
I'm Lieutenant
B'Elanna Torres
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
I am Automated
Unit 3-9-4-7.
Thank you for reactivating me,
Lieutenant B'Elanna Torres.
( dramatic theme playing )
TORRES: Chief Engineer's Log:
Supplemental.
The robot's power module
is continuing
to function normally,
using plasma
from our warp engines.
Repairing its systems
has taught me
more about robotics
than I ever could have learned
at Starfleet Academy.
( device chittering )
I think we're past
the critical stage.
I concur.
According to my
self-diagnostic systems,
Automated Personnel Unit 3947
is currently functioning
at 68% of peak
operating capabilities.
Automated Personnel
Unit 3947
is an extremely
well-designed machine.
Lieutenant B'Elanna Torres
is an extremely
proficient humanoid.
So how did you end up floating
in space so badly damaged?
I was operating
an asteroid-mining pod.
It exploded.
Do you know what
caused the explosion?
I am unable to access
that information.
My memory cells
are not yet functioning
at optimal efficiency.
Do you remember
where you come from?
I am stationed aboard
a Pralor vessel.
Well, we'll do our best
to find your ship
and return you
to your people.
Thank you.
I'm hoping that the memory loss
is only temporary.
Once the new plasma
has a chance
to fully integrate
into your systems,
I think you'll be
pretty close to... optimal.
The new plasma?
Yes, I adapted
your power module
to accept our warp plasma
as an energy source.
You repaired my power module?
Are you a Builder?
A Builder?
Well, I guess
you could say that.
I'm an engineer.
I'm responsible for repairing
and maintaining
all the systems on the ship.
Only the Builders
were capable
of constructing or repairing
power modules.
The Builders are...
the people who created you?
Yes.
And they're humanoids?
Like me?
Yes. Like Lieutenant
B'Elanna Torres.
You could create
a new power module.
You don't need
a new module.
The one I just fixed
will work fine now.
The new power module
will not be for me.
It will be a prototype
for the construction
of additional
automated units.
Can't the Builders make
additional units?
The Builders no longer exist.
Apparently, thousands of them
were built as service modules.
But the race who created them--
these Builders--
were killed off
decades ago in a war.
Leaving the automated units
to fend for themselves.
Now they're wearing out,
breaking down.
They've learned to make
repairs for themselves--
some pretty complex.
But the construction
of a power module--
the device
which sustains them--
is beyond their grasp.
It's... an incredible
challenge, Captain.
But with enough time
to study their systems
I might be able
to do it.
I don't doubt
your abilities, B'Elanna,
but helping them reproduce
is a clear violation
of the Prime Directive.
They've expressed
a desire to procreate.
That's basic
to any lifeform.
I'm not saying
they don't have the same rights
as any organic species.
That's not the issue here.
Are you sure?
Suppose
they were organic.
But they
had become sterile.
And we had a treatment
that would enable them
to start reproducing again.
Would you withhold
that treatment?
Maybe. I'd have to know more
about the circumstances.
But we're not talking
about treating
a disorder here, are we?
What's the difference?
Unlike a species
that's become sterile,
these robots never had
the ability to reproduce.
What you're talking about
is giving them new abilities,
which is the equivalent
of altering
their genetic structure.
To correct a flaw.
You can't call it
a flaw.
This is the way
they were designed.
I'm trying to save them
from extinction.
Unfortunately, extinction is
often the natural end of
evolution.
So you'll just willing to let
their entire society die off?
We don't know
that's going to happen.
If they're adaptable as you say,
and capable of educating
themselves,
they might learn to build a
power module themselves someday.
"Someday" could be
too late.
There are only a few
hundred of them left.
I feel for
the robots' plight.
But what you're proposing
is exactly the kind of tampering
the Prime Directive
prohibits.
We know almost nothing
about these creatures,
or the race
that built them.
What would be the consequences
of increasing their population?
Both to their own civilization
and others in this quadrant?
Who are we
to swoop in, play god,
and then continue on our way
without the slightest
consideration
of the the long-term effects
of our actions?
Captain...
B'Elanna, I share
your scientific curiosity,
and I admire your compassion,
but the answer is no.
I do not concur
with your captain's decision.
She's following
our Prime Directive.
Define
"Prime Directive."
It forbids us
to interfere
in the natural development
of other cultures.
The automated units
were not created naturally.
We were built.
You could help us
build more.
Captain Janeway
doesn't think
that's a good idea.
But Lieutenant
B'Elanna Torres does.
Maybe...
I don't know...
I'd like to try...
but I can't.
Without your help,
we will not survive.
( sighs )
I thought Lieutenant
B'Elanna Torres
was a Builder.
So did I.
We've located your ship.
We should be in communications
range in about an hour.
Thank you.
The alien vessel is entering
visual range, Captain.
Yellow Alert.
Slow to one-quarter impulse.
Put them on screen,
Ensign Kim.
KIM: Aye, Captain.
JANEWAY: Magnify.
TUVOK:
We're being scanned, Captain.
That's all right.
Let them take a look.
Open the channel.
Pralor Automated
Personnel Unit 6263
requests you identify
yourselves.
I'm Captain
Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
What are your intentions,
Captain Kathryn Janeway?
We rescued
one of your crew members--
Unit 3947-- and we'd like
to return him to your ship.
We'll prepare
to receive the unit.
Thank you
for your assistance.
Very polite,
these automated units.
Captain Janeway
gave me permission
to give you some
extra warp plasma
in case the plasma
we've infused into
your system
starts to degrade.
Thank you.
And you'll have to re-modulate
the anodyne relays periodically.
You are
repeating instructions
you have
already given me, B'Elanna.
I'm just making sure.
Well, I guess
this is good-bye.
( grunts in pain )
What are you doing?
( gasps )
Captain, I'm detecting a
chromo-dynamic energy discharge
in Transporter Room Two.
Bridge to
Transporter Room Two.
Janeway to Torres.
( scanner chittering )
Captain, someone's
initiating a transport.
It's Torres
and the robot.
Override.
I can't block it.
Their patterns are already
in the buffer.
They're gone, Captain.
Transport her
back now, Mr. Kim.
KIM: I can't get
a lock on her.
TUVOK: They have erected
some sort of
subspace defense
field around their vessel.
Our targeting scanners
cannot penetrate it.
Hail them.
KIM: They're not
responding.
Open a channel
on wide-band subspace.
Channel open.
This is Captain Janeway.
Your abduction
of our crew member
is a clear act of aggression.
If you do not return her
immediately,
we will be forced
to retaliate.
Confirm that they've received
the transmission, Mr. Kim.
They heard us all right.
They're just not answering.
Mr. Tuvok,
power the forward phaser banks.
What the hell
is going on here?
This is where
you will assist
in the creation
of the prototype.
I told you
I can't help you!
Now return me to my ship.
That is not possible.
Torres to Voyager.
Your communication device
has been deactivated.
I do not wish to
injure you, B'Elanna.
I helped you.
I reactivated you.
Why are you doing this?
We require additional
automated units
to prevent
our extinction.
Captain Janeway won't let you
get away with this!
It would be inadvisable
for your captain to provoke us.
Still no response, Captain.
Mr. Tuvok, any luck
penetrating their
defense field?
Negative.
Commander, is there
any sign that they're
preparing to attack?
Their shielding is making it
difficult to get clear readings.
I can't even tell you what
their weapons capabilities are.
Mr. Tuvok, I don't want you
to hit their ship,
but I do want you to open a hole
in their shielding
wide enough
to transport through.
Understood.
Mr. Kim,
match the targeting scanners
to the coordinates
of the phaser fire,
and stand by
to beam B'Elanna back.
Phasers calibrated.
Fire.
Their field strength
is down to 80%.
That's progress.
Fire again.
( deep rumbling )
Initiating evasive pattern
Omega Six.
They're firing
some kind of
quantum resonance charges,
Captain.
Our aft shields
are down to 53% and dropping.
Rerouting power
to aft shields.
Down to 24%.
Switching evasive pattern
to Theta One.
Lieutenant Tuvok, load
torpedo bays one through four
and stand by to fire
on my order.
Your captain has made
a tactical error
by attacking us.
Our weapons systems
are substantially
superior to yours.
Your shields are failing.
Your weapons pose
no threat to us.
Aft shields
have been penetrated.
We've got
to get out of here.
Agreed.
We'll try to come back
for B'Elanna later.
Do it, Mr. Paris.
Warp Three.
Propulsion systems are off-line.
We're dead in the water.
( alarm blaring )
Hull breach on Deck Six.
Initiating
emergency containment field.
Environmental control systems
are failing.
Oxygen levels
on decks three through seven
have dropped to Critical.
We've lost artificial gravity
on Deck Eight.
Injury reports from all decks.
( rumbling impact )
( Janeway grunts )
You've got to stop this.
Your ship opened fire.
We are programmed
to defend ourselves.
They're helpless.
Can't you see that?
Our enemies
must be destroyed.
We a not your enemies.
You are not
my enemy, B'Elanna,
but your captain is,
and your crew
follows her commands.
Captain Janeway
backed me
when I wanted
to reactivate you,
over the objections of
her Chief Security Officer.
You wouldn't be here
if it weren't for her.
All right.
If that's what it will take
to stop this, I'll do it.
I'll build your
damned prototype.
We're losing
life support, Captain.
The robots have powered down
their weapons systems.
They're hailing us, Captain.
On screen.
Captain,
is everybody okay?
We'll be all right.
What about you?
( sighs )
I've agreed to help them
build their prototype.
Lieutenant...
I know how you feel
about this, Captain.
I don't like it either,
but if I don't do it,
they'll destroy Voyager.
What choice do I have?
UNIT 3947: These are all
the materials necessary
to construct
a prototype unit.
You will be provided
with whatever additional
tools and equipment
you require.
You may access our database
and schematic information
from this computer terminal,
but it will not allow you
to interface
with any critical systems.
While you're on board,
you will have no contact
with your ship,
nor will you leave
this room.
I will remain here
to supervise your work.
You may proceed.
Proceed. Right.
But the question is,
where do I proceed from?
Let me ask you this.
Have any of you ever tried
to build a prototype?
We have tried,
and failed.
What was the problem?
I am unable to explain
the failure.
We duplicated a power module
to exact specifications
on several occasions,
but in all instances
the energy output of the new
module was insufficient to
operate a unit.
And you're sure you reproduced
the module exactly?
This is a schematic
of a power module
from a terminated unit.
This one is from
a failed prototype.
They are identical.
There is no reason why one
should function while
the other does not.
Unit 3947,
what can you report?
Well, let's see.
We've been working
for about five minutes.
So, I guess we don't have
a lot of progress to report.
Our sensors indicate
that the humanoid vessel
will require approximately
140 hours to repair.
It is necessary for
you to complete work
on the prototype
before that time.
Why? We don't seem to be
any match for you.
Our tactical subprocessors
indicate a 79% likelihood
that a rescue
will be attempted
once sufficient repairs
are completed.
At optimal efficiency,
your engines are more
powerful than ours.
It is also possible
that these humanoids
will not make decisions
based on tactical probabilities.
Their cognitive process
is... unpredictable.
We will remain on
full tactical alert.
The humanoid may
purposefully attempt
to delay completion
of the prototype,
hoping
she will be rescued.
I don't know if a promise
means anything to you people,
but it does to us.
I gave you my word
that I'd do my best. And I will.
According to my observations,
the humanoid is operating
at optimal efficiency.
Thank you.
But I have to tell you,
there are no guarantees here.
Building a prototype
from scratch
is a lot different
than repairing
a broken power module.
I don't even know
if it's possible.
If you fail,
you and your people will die.
B'Elanna Torres,
6263 is
a designated command unit.
He is merely following
his programming.
I don't need to be threatened.
I told you I'd do my best.
I believe you,
but Unit 6263 does not.
He does not know Lieutenant
B'Elanna Torres as I do.
Let me see one of those
terminated power modules.
We've managed to repair
the hull breach,
but we have no power
on decks three through seven.
Aft shields are still
completely nonfunctional.
And last but not least,
the dilithium matrix
is destabilized,
so we can't get
the warp engines running.
We're talking about at least
another six days of repairs.
We're not sticking
around that long.
I want a plan to get
B'Elanna off that ship
before she can finish
building the prototype.
In that case,
I suggest
we make warp drive
our priority.
Any rescue attempt
will no doubt necessitate
a rapid departure.
Agreed.
Mr. Kim, can you give me
an estimate
on repairing
the dilithium matrix?
How does 72 hours sound?
Like 24 hours too long.
Dismissed.
TORRES: Hand me
the sub-micron scanner.
( whirring )
Phase coil resonator.
Well, I think I know why
your other prototypes failed,
but... I'm not sure I know
what to do about it yet.
Explain.
The automated units
are modular.
Your parts are identical,
interchangeable, right?
That is correct.
So...
If you lose an arm,
you can replace it
with another one,
and over the years, you've
learned to make new arms
because
they're all the same,
and your programming
is sophisticated enough
to allow you to reproduce
what you see,
but each power module
has a slightly different
energy signature,
so, even if you copy
this guy's module exactly,
it wouldn't work
in any other unit.
As far as I can tell,
every automated unit
has a power module with
a unique energy code.
Can you reprogram
the energy codes
to make the modules
interchangeable?
I don't think so.
You have failed.
I will inform 6263.
Hey!
Do all you
automated units give up
the minute you hit
a bump in the road?
Do you have
an alternative idea?
What we've got to do
is design
a standardized module
with a uniform energy code
that can power any unit.
According to my observations,
there is now sufficient reason
for greater optimism.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
TUVOK: Due to the complexity
of their defense field,
and our severe power shortage,
it is unlikely that we can
modify the transporters
to beam
Lieutenant Torres out.
But if we can maneuver
inside the field...
Our transporters
could get the job done.
Is that a
viable option?
For a shuttlecraft,
it may be.
They were able to knock
out Voyager's shields
in a matter of minutes.
A shuttle would be
even more vulnerable.
It would be advisable to create
a diversion of some sort.
To take their attention
away from the shuttle.
Attack them again?
I don't want to risk that
a second time.
I don't need
a diversion.
Just give me a chance.
I'll get her out of there.
You don't mind if
we give you a little
help, do you, Paris?
I'd hate to lose
another shuttle.
Your concern
for my welfare
is heartwarming.
In another 12 hours
our warp engines
will be back on line.
I'd like to come up
with a diversion
before then.
Okay, gentlemen?
So far, so good.
I'm not getting any feedback
from the motor circuits.
You going to be
the obstetrician
of this unit, 3947?
Please rephrase
the question.
If this works,
will you be in charge
of assembling the new units?
I am programmed
as a ships maintenance unit.
I have no knowledge of design,
nor do any of the other
automated personnel.
Sounds like you just
volunteered for new duty.
I hope you're
watching closely.
I am observing your work.
However, I do not possess
your improvisational
capabilities.
Well, once we have
the prototype,
all you'd have to do is copy it.
Tell me
something, 39.
Can I call you 39?
I am Automated Unit 3947.
Fine.
3947,
did you wake up
on a bench like this one?
How long have you been alive?
I have been in service
1,314,807 hours
and 33 minutes.
I was activated by a Builder
from the Pralor homeworld.
Tell me something more
about these Builders.
Were they anything like us?
I have insufficient knowledge
of your culture
to provide an adequate response.
Will you provide
additional information?
Well, I asked
about your culture.
Only fair
you should ask about mine.
Does your culture include
artificial life-forms?
As a matter of fact, it does.
Are they similar
to the automated personnel
units aboard this ship?
Well, they come
in different shapes and sizes.
Some have limbs, some don't.
Most don't have
your cognitive abilities.
Are they your servants?
Well, I guess you could say
that the robots we use
are servants,
in a manner of speaking.
But they aren't sentient
like you.
In fact, we have
only one sentient
artificial life-form
in our society,
and he is treated
the same as any human.
The same. He is equal
to a Builder?
That's right.
He works on a ship
just like you and I.
He wears the same uniform I do.
What is his designant number?
He has a name,
like the rest of us. "Data."
Data. I would like
to be acquainted with this Data.
Well, it looks like this
standardized power module
is working pretty well so far.
You will succeed,
B'Elanna Torres.
Don't send me flowers yet.
I've still got to see
whether it will power
an actual unit.
I believe it will.
We're making progress
on the dilithium matrix.
It should be stable enough
to reinitialize the warp core
in about six hours.
Good. What about
our diversion?
Any suggestions?
When we were in the Maquis,
B'Elanna once linked
a holoemitter
to a deflector array
and projected an image
of another ship into space.
I like it.
But do we have enough power?
We will by the time
the warp core's on line.
I already have Kim working on
the holodeck...
Tuvok to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
I'm picking up
an unidentified alien ship
on long-range sensors.
It's heading
for our coordinates.
We're on our way.
Well, it fits.
Cross your fingers.
So far, so good.
Let's hope it can interface
with the unit.
( unit powers up )
( power fails )
It does
not function correctly.
It does not function
correctly yet.
Your builders
should have programmed you
with a little more patience.
I'm going to try adjusting
the flux capacitance.
( unit powers up )
Prototype Unit 0001 is ready
to accept programming.
We did it.
We actually did it.
You did it,
B'Elanna Torres.
I knew this task
would not exceed
your operating
capabilities.
Prototype Unit 0001
is ready to accept programming.
What are you doing?
I am congratulating you!
You're a father.
( laughing )
( rumbling )
No sign of organic life
aboard that ship either.
They appear to be manned
by automated units
virtually identical to those
operating the first ship.
Is it possible
that we've stumbled
into the middle
of some kind of... robotic war?
( dramatic theme playing )
We've got to get
Torres back now.
Agreed, but first I want
to show both those ships
this isn't our fight.
Ease us back on maneuvering
thrusters, Mr. Paris,
nice and steady.
The second ship
is hailing us.
On screen.
Cravic Automated Commander 122
requests you identify yourself.
My name
is Kathryn Janeway,
Captain of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
Withdraw from this area
immediately.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
One of my crew members
is being held hostage
aboard the Pralor vessel.
I won't leave without her.
Remain at
your present coordinates
and don't attempt to intervene,
or you will be fired on.
Captain,
this new ship could be a...
The diversion
we've been looking for.
Mr. Kim, what's the status
of our warp engines?
We're still an hour
away at best.
We may not have an hour.
Get down to Engineering.
Be ready to give me
as much power as you can
the minute we get Torres back.
Aye, Captain.
If those two ships
keep each other busy,
we may not need warp
to get away.
Mr. Paris, report
to the Shuttle Bay.
Yes, ma'am.
Chakotay,
you have the con.
Who are they?
Automated personnel units
of the Cravic homeworld.
Robots from
another world?
That is correct.
Why are they
attacking you?
They were programmed to
do so by their builders.
Prototype Unit 0001
is ready to accept programming.
The Cravic Builders,
the Pralor Builders--
Were they enemies?
That is correct.
Look, maybe Captain Janeway
can contact the Cravic leaders
and convince them
to stop the fighting, then...
That is not possible.
Why not?
The Cravic are also extinct.
I'm approaching the perimeter
of the defense field.
TUVOK:
Acknowledged.
Rotate your
shield harmonics
until
they are synchronized
with the frequency
of the field.
Shields synchronized.
I'm going in.
( shuttle struck by weapon )
Then again, maybe not.
It didn't work.
He bounced right
off the field.
Mr. Paris, re-set your heading
for coordinates 105.
Mark 4-0.
Uh, if I understand you, Tuvok,
that would take me
into a direct line of fire
with the Cravic ship.
Precisely.
The concentration of fire
is opening a rift
in the Pralor defense field.
Which I just might be able
to sneak through
if I can dodge
a disruptor blast or two.
Changing heading.
If both sides
were annihilated,
then why continue
your war?
3947: All automated
personnel units
were programmed
to achieve victory.
Prototype Unit 0001
is ready to accept programming.
The Cravic ship has penetrated
our defense shield.
Has anyone
in all these years
ever tried
to stop this war?
The Pralor and the Cravic
called a truce.
Wait a minute, if both sides
called a truce,
then why didn't they
stop you from fighting?
They attempted to do so.
And?
We terminated the Builders.
( dramatic theme playing )
Paris to Voyager.
I'm approaching the entry point.
Acknowledged.
Showing a rift
in the defense field
off your starboard bow.
I'm on it.
When it was anticipated
that the war would end,
the Builders no longer
required our services
and they attempted
to terminate us.
In doing so,
they became the enemy.
We are programmed
to destroy the enemy.
It is necessary
for our survival.
Now that you have
constructed the prototype,
we will soon outnumber
the Cravic units.
We will achieve victory.
( Torres grunts )
This is 3947.
Fire units, report
to the Reconstruction Bay
Number One.
The individual energy codes--
is that why
the Builders added them--
to prevent
the procreation of these units?
( gasps )
My God, what have I done?
Prototype Unit 0001
is ready to accept programming.
( zapping )
( warbling speech )
( grunts )
You have terminated
the prototype.
Yes. I have.
You will build another.
Never.
Lieutenant B'Elanna Torres,
I told 6263
you were not our enemy.
I never wanted to be your enemy.
I'm sorry.
Shuttle to Voyager.
I've got her, but she's injured.
Tell the doctor to stand by.
Beam her out as soon as
I clear the defense field.
Acknowledged, Mr. Paris.
The ships are continuing
to exchange fire, Captain.
They are ignoring
the shuttle.
Bridge to Engineering.
Stand by, warp engines.
We'll engage
the moment Mr. Paris gets back.
Aye, Captain.
( dramatic theme playing )
One pot of Landras blend,
compliments of the chef.
Mm. I never thought
Neelix's coffee
could taste so good.
I'll tell him
you said so.
( sighs )
I don't know what to say.
As far as I'm concerned,
you did what you thought
was necessary
to ensure the safety
of this crew.
Thank you.
It must have been difficult.
Difficult?
To destroy what you created.
It was necessary.
I read your report.
It was no small achievement,
B'Elanna.
You gave that unit life.
You should have
seen it, Captain.
It was incredible.
I installed that module,
and the prototype
looked up at me
and asked me
for programming.
As I said,
it must have been difficult.
It was necessary.
( dramatic theme playing )
( dramatic
theme music playing )