CAPTAIN.
REPORT.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE KAZON
HAVE RETREATED, CAPTAIN.
WE MUST HAVE HURT THEM.
NOT AS BAD
AS THEY HURT US.
ALL ENGINES ARE OFF LINE.
CAPTAIN, SHIELDS ARE DOWN,
AS ARE ALL WEAPONS ARRAYS.
WE'D BETTER HOPE
THEY DON'T COME BACK.
WE'RE SITTING DUCKS.
JANEWAY TO ENGINEERING.
WHAT'S YOUR STATUS?
WE'RE IN BAD SHAPE, CAPTAIN.
WE HAD TO SHUT DOWN THE WARP
ENGINES TO AVOID A BREACH.
THE IMPULSE ENGINES
ARE GONE TOO.
I THINK
I CAN GIVE YOU THRUSTERS
BUT I'VE GOT
A LOT OF CASUALTIES DOWN HERE
I'VE GOT TO TEND TO FIRST.
LIEUTENANT, IT'S
KURT BENDERA.
HE'S HURT PRETTY BAD.
NO.
HIS CONSOLE
EXPLODED
CAUGHT HIM RIGHT
IN THE FACE.
WE'VE GOT TO GET HIM
TO SICK BAY RIGHT AWAY.
TORRES TO SICK BAY.
I hope this is urgent,
Lieutenant.
WE HAVE OUR HANDS FULL
AT THE MOMENT.
I'm sending up
an emergency transport.
One of my people
is severely burned.
VERY WELL.
WE'LL DO WHAT WE CAN.
MORE DAMAGE REPORTS
COMING IN, CAPTAIN.
THERE'S A HULL BREACH
ON DECK FOUR.
FORCE FIELD'S
IN PLACE.
REPAIR CREW'S
ON THE WAY.
THERE'VE BEEN CASUALTIES
ON ALL DECKS.
NO FATALITIES
SO FAR.
CAPTAIN, REQUEST PERMISSION
TO GIVE TORRES A HAND
IN ENGINEERING.
MAYBE I CAN HELP
GET PROPULSION UP AND RUNNING.
GOOD IDEA. GO AHEAD.
CAPTAIN, MY
READINGS INDICATE
THE NAVIGATIONAL
DEFLECTOR
HAS SUSTAINED
MASSIVE DAMAGE.
IT WILL BE NECESSARY
TO REPAIR IT
BEFORE WE CAN ACHIEVE
MORE THAN THRUSTER POWER.
GET REPAIR CREWS ON IT.
MR. KIM, I WANT
A COMPLETE ANALYSIS
OF ALL THE DAMAGE
WE'VE SUSTAINED.
YES, MA'AM.
HE'S NOT RESPONDING.
75 MILLIGRAMS OF IMPEDREZENE.
THAT MIGHT HELP STIMULATE
HIS CARDIAC FUNCTIONS
BUT HE'S SUSTAINED SO MUCH
INJURY IT MAY BE TOO LATE.
IT HAD NO EFFECT.
CORTICAL STIMULATOR.
I'M SORRY.
HE WAS TOO BADLY INJURED.
HE SAVED MY LIFE ONCE...
NEAR THE CARDASSIAN BORDER.
( door beeping )
COME IN.
CREWMAN BENDERA IS DEAD.
THE DOCTOR
COULDN'T DO ANYTHING.
I'M SORRY, CHAKOTAY.
I KNOW YOU WERE FRIENDS.
WILL YOU ARRANGE
A MEMORIAL SERVICE?
I'LL GET RIGHT ON IT.
WAS THERE
SOMETHING ELSE?
YES.
LIKE IT OR NOT
IT SEEMS WE'RE IN A SITUATION
WHERE THE RULES HAVE CHANGED
AND MAYBE, IF WE'RE GOING
TO SURVIVE OUT HERE
WE HAVE TO START CHANGING TOO.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHEN WE FIRST STARTED
OUR TRIP HOME
YOU MADE A CONSCIOUS DECISION
TO TREAT VOYAGER
AS A STARFLEET SHIP
WITH A STARFLEET CREW
FOLLOWING STARFLEET RULES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
STARFLEET WORKS WELL
IN THE ALPHA QUADRANT.
BUT OUT HERE...
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE THINKING
MORE LIKE THE MAQUIS.
THE MAQUIS HAD TO SURVIVE
ON THEIR OWN.
WE WERE UP AGAINST
INSURMOUNTABLE ODDS.
WE HAD TO CREATE OUR OWN
OPPORTUNITIES FOR SUCCESS
BECAUSE NOBODY WAS WILLING
TO HELP US.
SOUND LIKE ANYBODY YOU KNOW?
IF YOU'RE SUGGESTING
WE ABANDON OUR PRINCIPLES
JUST BECAUSE
WE'RE OUT OF HAILING RANGE...
CAPTAIN, THIS WAS THE FOURTH
ATTACK IN TWO WEEKS.
WE'VE LOST THREE CREW MEMBERS
TO THE KAZON.
A DOZEN MORE HAVE SUSTAINED
SERIOUS INJURIES.
THIS SHIP HAS TAKEN
SO MUCH DAMAGE
WE'LL BE LUCKY TO GET WARP DRIVE
ON LINE AGAIN.
AND WE CAN
COUNT ON THE FACT
THAT THE KAZON WILL BE BACK.
I DON'T THINK WE CAN AFFORD
TO KEEP DOING BUSINESS AS USUAL.
A LOT OF US CAN SAY
WE'RE ALIVE TODAY
BECAUSE OF KURT BENDERA.
THERE WAS NEVER A BETTER MAN
TO HAVE AT YOUR SIDE
NEVER ANYONE MORE WILLING
TO TAKE ON THE TOUGH JOBS.
THE FIRST TIME I MET HIM
WAS IN A MINING COMMUNITY
ON TELFAS PRIME.
SOME OF THE MINERS OBJECTED
TO MY SENSE OF HUMOR
AND DECIDED THEY SHOULD BREAK
A FEW OF MY BONES.
THERE WERE FOUR OF THEM
AND ONE OF ME
AND I WAS TAKING A BEATING.
SUDDENLY, THIS MAN I'D NEVER
SEEN BEFORE CAME OUT OF NOWHERE
AND EVENED THINGS UP.
WE STOOD BACK TO BACK
AND PRETTY SOON
THE OTHERS DECIDED
MY SENSE OF HUMOR
WASN'T SO BAD AFTER ALL.
I THANKED THE MAN,
AND HE JUST GRINNED
AND SAID,
"I LIKE A GOOD FIGHT."
HE WAS MY FRIEND
FROM THAT MOMENT ON.
AND HE KEPT FIGHTING
THE GOOD FIGHT
RIGHT UP TO THE END.
I'LL MISS HIM.
ENSIGN.
CAPTAIN, CAN I
ASK YOU SOMETHING?
OF COURSE.
NOW THAT THE KAZON
HAVE STEPPED UP THEIR ATTACKS
A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK THAT WE
ARE NOT GOING TO MAKE IT OUT OF
HERE ALIVE.
I'D LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT YOU HAVE
TO SAY ABOUT THAT.
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU
HAVE TO SAY ABOUT THAT?
I ASSURE YOU, YOU
CAN SPEAK FREELY.
I'D GIVE THEM
WHAT THEY WANT.
I'LL GIVE THEM THE REPLICATORS
AND THE TRANSPORTERS
AND WHATEVER ELSE
IT IS THEY'RE AFTER.
I'M SURE YOU REALIZE THAT
WOULD BE A VIOLATION OF...
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
THE PRIME DIRECTIVE
BUT, YOU KNOW WHAT?
THE FEDERATION IS 70,000
LIGHT YEARS AWAY.
WHAT DOES IT MATTER
WHAT THESE PEOPLE DO
TO EACH OTHER
WITH OUR TECHNOLOGY?
I APPRECIATE
YOUR CONCERNS, CREWMAN
BUT LET ME MAKE IT
ABSOLUTELY CLEAR--
I'LL DESTROY THIS SHIP
BEFORE I TURN ANY PART OF IT
OVER TO THE KAZON.
SO THAT'S HOW THE MAQUIS
WOULD DO IT, HMM?
IT'S ALL RIGHT, COMMANDER.
I KNOW HOGAN'S UPSET.
HE AND BENDERA WERE CLOSE.
BUT THAT'S NOT WHY HE THINKS
WE SHOULD GIVE THE KAZON
WHAT THEY WANT.
I THINK I'VE MADE MY
POSITION CLEAR ON THAT.
YOU HAVE, BUT A LOT
OF THE CREW FEEL
THEY HAVEN'T HAD THE CHANCE
TO VOICE THEIR OPINIONS.
THIS ISN'T A DEMOCRACY,
CHAKOTAY.
I CAN'T RUN THIS
SHIP BY CONSENSUS.
A LOT OF THE MAQUIS FEEL
THE FEDERATION
ABANDONED THEM YEARS AGO.
YOU MAY BE WILLING TO DIE
FOR FEDERATION PRINCIPLES
BUT THEY'RE NOT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'D
SUPPORT THAT MAN'S POSITION.
I DON'T,
BUT ISN'T THERE SOMETHING
IN BETWEEN
YOUR POSITION AND HIS?
DECK THREE.
ALL I'M SAYING, CAPTAIN,
IS THAT MAYBE THERE'S
A LITTLE ROOM FOR FLEXIBILITY
IN INTERPRETING
STARFLEET'S PROTOCOLS.
FRANKLY, I'M NOT SURE
THEY WERE EVER INTENDED
FOR SITUATIONS LIKE THIS.
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANY EVIDENCE
THAT THEY'VE LET US DOWN.
MAYBE THIS SITUATION WITH
THE KAZON IS THE FIRST EXAMPLE.
MAYBE WE HAVE TO EXAMINE
STARFLEET'S PRINCIPLES
WITH A COLD EYE
AND ASK OURSELVES
IF THEY'RE REALLY
APPLICABLE HERE.
COMPUTER, HOLD TURBOLIFT.
COMMANDER, IF YOU HAVE
A SPECIFIC SUGGESTION
PLEASE FEEL FREE TO MAKE IT.
MAKE A DEAL--
AN ALLIANCE.
WITH THE KAZON?
WITH ONE OF THEIR FACTIONS,
OR TWO.
IF WE HAD THE OGLA
AND THE RELORA AS OUR ALLIES
THE OTHERS WOULD BE AFRAID
TO TOUCH US.
NOTHING WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
WITH THE KAZON
WOULD LEAD ME TO BELIEVE
THEY'RE TRUSTWORTHY.
I CAN'T IMAGINE MAKING
A DEAL WITH THEM.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
MAYBE THAT'S BECAUSE
YOUR IMAGINATION IS LIMITED
BY STARFLEET PROTOCOLS.
AS CAPTAIN, YOU'RE RESPONSIBLE
FOR MAKING DECISIONS
IN THE BEST INTEREST
OF YOUR CREW
AND I THINK YOU HAVE
TO ASK YOURSELF...
IF YOU'RE DOING THAT.
( door beeps )
COME IN.
CAPTAIN.
THIS IS UNEXPECTED.
I'VE BEEN IN YOUR
QUARTERS BEFORE.
INDEED, BUT SO RARELY
THAT I CAN REMEMBER
EACH INSTANCE.
VULCAN SPICE TEA-- HOT.
AND IT WAS ALWAYS AT
A TIME WHEN YOU WERE
PARTICULARLY TROUBLED.
RIGHT, AS USUAL.
THANK YOU.
COMMANDER CHAKOTAY
HAS PROPOSED
THAT WE MAKE AN ALLIANCE
WITH ONE OF THE KAZON FACTIONS.
WE WOULDN'T GIVE THEM
WEAPONS OR TECHNOLOGY
BUT WE WOULD PLEDGE
TO SUPPORT AND DEFEND THEM
IF THEY'RE ATTACKED.
I AM SURE THAT MADE
YOU UNCOMFORTABLE.
HOW CAN I CONSIDER IT?
I CAN'T JUST WALK AWAY
FROM THE PRECEPTS
STARFLEET HAS LAID OUT
FOR US--
YOU DON'T DEAL WITH OUTLAWS;
YOU DON'T INVOLVE YOURSELF
IN THE POLITICAL MACHINATIONS
OF OTHER CULTURES.
IT GOES AGAINST
EVERYTHING I BELIEVE,
EVERYTHING I'VE TRAINED FOR,
EVERYTHING EXPERIENCE
HAS TAUGHT ME.
QUITE RIGHT.
DO I HEAR
A "HOWEVER" COMING?
YOU ARE PERCEPTIVE, CAPTAIN.
I BELIEVE COMMANDER
CHAKOTAY'S SUGGESTION
DOES HAVE MERIT.
HELP ME UNDERSTAND THAT.
WHEN I WAS A YOUNG MAN,
A GREAT VISIONARY
NAMED SPOCK RECOMMENDED AN
ALLIANCE BETWEEN THE FEDERATION
AND THE KLINGON EMPIRE.
THIS PRODUCED A MAJOR DISPUTE.
THE KLINGONS, AFTER ALL,
WERE OUTLAWS
EMPLOYING VIOLENCE AND BRUTALITY
IN ORDER TO BUILD THEIR EMPIRE.
I MYSELF SPOKE OUT
AGAINST SUCH A COALITION.
BUT THE ALLIANCE WAS FORGED,
AND IT BROUGHT A STABILITY
TO THE QUADRANT
THAT HAD NOT BEEN THERE
FOR 200 YEARS.
SPOCK'S SUGGESTION,
SO CONTROVERSIAL AT FIRST,
PROVED TO BE THE CORNERSTONE
OF PEACE.
THERE ARE SOME DIFFERENCES HERE.
BY ALLYING OURSELVES
TO ONE FACTION.
WE'D BE GIVING THAT FACTION
MORE POWER THAN THE OTHERS.
THAT WOULD CLEARLY AFFECT
THE INTERNAL POLITICS
OF ALL THE KAZON.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR CONCERN.
BUT REMEMBER, IT WOULD ONLY BE
A TEMPORARY ARRANGEMENT,
SINCE WE ARE ON OUR WAY
OUT OF THIS QUADRANT.
IN THE MEANTIME,
IT MIGHT BRING STABILITY
TO THE REGION
AND SECURITY FOR US.
ONCE WE'RE GONE,
THEY'LL PROBABLY GO BACK
TO THEIR INFIGHTING.
PERHAPS.
BUT EVEN TEMPORARY STABILITY
CAN BRING AN APPRECIATION
FOR PEACE.
THIS FLOWER
IS A RARE HYBRID.
AS FAR AS I KNOW, IT EXISTS
NOWHERE ELSE IN THE GALAXY.
I CREATED IT BY
GRAFTING A CUTTING
FROM A SOUTH AMERICAN ORCHID
ONTO A VULCAN FAVANIT PLANT.
I DOUBTED THE GRAFT
WOULD TAKE.
AND INDEED, THE PLANT
WAS SICKLY AT FIRST.
HOWEVER, AFTER
A FEW WEEKS,
BOTH PLANTS ADAPTED
TO THEIR NEW CONDITION
AND, IN FACT,
BECAME STRONGER
THAN EITHER
HAD BEEN ALONE.
CONSEQUENTLY,
AFTER MUCH CONSIDERATION,
I'VE DECIDED TO SEEK AN ALLIANCE
WITH ONE OF THE KAZON FACTIONS.
CAPTAIN, YOU
CAN'T BE SERIOUS.
THIS GOES AGAINST...
ENSIGN...
I'LL BE GLAD TO DISCUSS
MY REASONING WITH YOU
AT A MORE APPROPRIATE TIME.
HOWEVER, THIS MEETING IS
NOT TO DEBATE THE DECISION,
BUT TO DECIDE
HOW TO PURSUE IT.
CAPTAIN... IF I MAY.
YES, MR. NEELIX.
WE'RE NOT FAR FROM A
PLANET KNOWN AS SOBRAS,
WHERE THERE'S A
KAZON SETTLEMENT
INHABITED BY A FACTION
KNOWN AS THE POMMAR.
I HAVE AN ACQUAINTANCE
THERE--
SOMEONE WHO OWES
ME SOME FAVORS.
SOME RATHER LARGE FAVORS,
ACTUALLY.
PERHAPS I COULD
MEET WITH HIM
AND SOUND HIM OUT.
IS HE AUTHORIZED TO
SPEAK FOR HIS MAJE?
NOT EXACTLY,
BUT HE DOES HAVE
THE MAJE'S EAR.
THIS WOULD BE
STRICTLY INFORMAL,
BUT IT MIGHT
GIVE US A READING
ON THE POSSIBILITY
WITHOUT THE RISK OF
ACTUAL CONFRONTATION.
GOOD IDEA.
PROCEED, MR. NEELIX.
WHY DON'T WE JUST
CONTACT SESKA AND
FORM AN ALLIANCE WITH HER?
ACTUALLY,
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
YOU'VE GOT
TO BE KIDDING.
NOT AT ALL.
SESKA HAS BEEN TRYING
TO FORGE AN ALLIANCE
AMONG THE KAZON.
SHE WOULD JUMP AT THE CHANCE
TO GET OUR SUPPORT.
SHE'S RIGHT.
IF WE WENT THROUGH SESKA
AT LEAST WE COULD ALLY OURSELVES
WITH THE NISTRIM.
I THINK IT'S A BAD IDEA.
YOU CAN'T HAVE IT
BOTH WAYS, COMMANDER.
IF YOU WANT TO GET IN
THE MUD WITH THE KAZON
YOU CAN'T START COMPLAINING
THAT YOU MIGHT GET DIRTY.
FINE. I'LL TALK WITH SESKA.
NO.
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
TOO MUCH WITH HER.
MR. NEELIX, PREPARE TO TAKE
YOUR SHUTTLE TO SOBRAS.
IN THE MEANTIME, I'LL
MAKE CONTACT WITH SESKA.
DISMISSED.
( sighs )
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 49337.4.
AFTER SENDING A SUBSPACE MESSAGE
TO SESKA
AND THE NISTRIM MAJE CULLAH,
WE HAVE A RECEIVED
A QUICK RESPONSE.
Captain Janeway.
Commander Chakotay.
I must say we were surprised
to hear from you.
ARE YOU WILLING
TO MEET WITH US?
You've made
an interesting proposal.
I've discussed it with Seska,
and she assures me
that you would not make
this gesture
unless you were sincere.
I will talk with you.
I SUGGEST WE RENDEZVOUS.
WE'LL TRANSMIT COORDINATES
TO YOU.
If you don't mind, Captain,
we'd prefer
to choose the coordinates.
FINE. TRANSMIT THEM TO US.
We'll meet in approximately
20 hours.
I must say, Captain,
I look forward
to this opportunity.
( sultry jazz playing )
HELLO, MY FRIENDS.
PLEASE, DON'T LET ME INTERRUPT.
I WAS HOPING TO FIND
MY GOOD FRIEND JAL TERSA HERE.
HAS HE BEEN IN TONIGHT?
THANK YOU.
TERSA, MY FRIEND.
IT COULD BE DANGEROUS
SNEAKING UP
ON A MAN LIKE THAT.
I'D NEVER DREAM
OF SNEAKING UP ON YOU
BUT YOU WERE
SO ENGROSSED IN...
WHATEVER IT IS
YOU'RE DOING...
A PUZZLE.
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE,
TALAXIAN?
I'M GOOD AT PUZZLES.
PERHAPS I COULD HELP.
THE DANCER SHOWED IT TO ME.
BY MOVING ONLY TWO RODS,
THIS DODECAHEDRON
CAN BECOME AN ICOSAHEDRON.
SHE SAID SHE'D SPEND THE NIGHT
WITH THE MAN WHO COULD SOLVE IT.
( growls )
A SPLENDID MOTIVATION,
TO BE SURE.
I JUST MIGHT BE ABLE
TO MAKE YOUR NIGHT
A MEMORABLE ONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO SOLVE THIS?
I MIGHT...
IF YOU'LL HEAR ME OUT FIRST.
MY FORTUNE'S HAVE CHANGED
SINCE WE LAST MET, TERSA.
I'VE BECOME A PERSON OF
SOME INFLUENCE ABOARD A
STARSHIP KNOWN AS VOYAGER.
( sighs )
YOU MUST THINK US VERY ISOLATED.
EVERYONE KNOWS THAT.
IT'S PROBABLY THE ONLY REASON
YOU WERE ALLOWED IN HERE,
ESPECIALLY AFTER LAST TIME.
OUCH.
A SIMPLE MISUNDERSTANDING.
UH... TERSA, I KNOW YOU HAVE
THE EAR OF YOUR FIRST MAJE,
AS I DO OF OUR CAPTAIN.
WE COULD BE QUITE USEFUL
TO BOTH OF THEM.
GO ON.
MY CAPTAIN IS INTERESTED IN
TALKING TO YOUR MAJE
TO DISCUSS A POSSIBLE ALLIANCE.
DO YOU THINK HE'D HAVE
ANY INTEREST IN SUCH A MEETING?
AN ALLIANCE?
BETWEEN THE KAZON-POMMAR
AND THE FEDERATIONS?
AN INTERESTING THOUGHT,
ISN'T IT?
YOU'RE COMING WITH US.
TERSA, EXPLAIN TO THEM.
WE'RE FRIENDS.
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHO THIS PERSON IS.
SOME LUNATIC WHO SAT DOWN
AND STARTED BABBLING.
I GUESS YOU'LL BE SPENDING
THE NIGHT ALONE.
YOU'VE MADE A GOOD CHOICE.
THE NISTRIM WILL BE
A POTENT ALLY.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THE NISTRIM
WILL ALSO BE AN HONORABLE ALLY,
THAT YOU'LL ADHERE
TO THE CONDITIONS
WE ESTABLISH.
YOU CAN LET
ALL THE KAZON FACTIONS KNOW
THAT VOYAGER HAS FORMED
A COALITION WITH YOU
AND WILL BE AN ALLY
TO ANY NISTRIM SHIP
OR OUTPOST WE ENCOUNTER.
IN ADDITION, WE'RE PREPARED
TO PROVIDE EMERGENCY SUPPLIES
WHEN NEEDED--
FOOD, MEDICINE, CLOTHING.
WHAT WE WILL NOT PROVIDE
IS ANY OF OUR TECHNOLOGY
OR WEAPONRY.
UNDERSTOOD.
JUST ONE OTHER DETAIL...
AN EXCHANGE OF CREW MEMBERS.
AN EXCHANGE?
YES.
I'M SURE YOU'LL AGREE
THAT OUR ALLIANCE
SHOULD REPRESENT
A GENUINE PARTNERSHIP.
PERHAPS YOU SHOULD
DEFINE THAT.
IT'S OBVIOUS.
FEDERATION CREW ON MY SHIP.
NISTRIM CREW ON YOURS.
MAJE, I THINK THAT'S A DETAIL
WE COULD WORK OUT LATER.
I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT I WOULD NEVER AGREE
TO THAT.
IT SEEMS A NATURAL EXTENSION
OF YOUR OWN PROPOSAL.
WE DON'T HAVE TO DECIDE
EVERYTHING RIGHT NOW.
I WILL DETERMINE
WHAT WE DECIDE AND WHEN.
YES, MAJE.
I WON'T HAVE A WOMAN
DICTATE TERMS TO ME.
CULLAH...
I FOUND THE IDEA OF
AN ALLIANCE WITH
YOU DISTASTEFUL.
I WAS WILLING TO EXPLORE
THE POSSIBILITY
BUT NOW I SEE MY INSTINCTS
WERE DEAD ON.
TALK TO HER.
TELL HER
TO BE REASONABLE.
THIS MEETING IS OVER.
AS SOON AS YOUR MAJE LEARNS
I'M BEING IMPRISONED
HE'LL BE OUTRAGED!
HURRY UP.
HE WON'T LOOK KINDLY
ON ANYONE WHO'S MADE
SUCH AN EGREGIOUS ERROR.
WHAT ARE YOU CHARGING ME WITH?!
HOW LONG WILL I BE HELD?
MOVE.
I ASSUME YOU'LL AT LEAST LET ME
CONFER WITH COUNSEL.
I HAVE THE ABILITY
TO REWARD HANDSOMELY ANYONE
WHO SHOWS ME
A BIT OF UNDERSTANDING.
( crying )
IS THAT A BABY?
MY NAME IS NEELIX.
I-I'M TALAXIAN.
I'M MABUS.
MY FRIENDS AND I ARE TRABE.
THEY HURT YOU.
I WASN'T WALKING
QUICKLY ENOUGH FOR THEM.
LET'S GET
THE BLEEDING STOPPED.
THEN I'LL CLEAN IT.
WHY ARE THEY
HOLDING YOU?
THEY SEEM TO BE DETAINING
ANYONE WHO ISN'T KAZON.
SEVERAL OF OUR GROUP
HAVE BEEN TAKEN FOR QUESTIONING,
BUT SO FAR, NONE OF THEM
HAVE COME BACK.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
FIVE DAYS.
THEY ATTACKED US IN SPACE.
20 OF OUR GROUP DIED.
WE'VE LOST NINE MORE
SINCE THEY PUT US IN PRISON
INCLUDING MOST OF
THE GOVERNING COUNCIL.
I'M THE ONLY ONE LEFT.
THE KAZON WON'T BE SATISFIED
UNTIL YOU'VE ALL
BEEN ANNIHILATED.
IF WE'VE LEARNED ANYTHING,
IT'S HOW TO SURVIVE.
DID YOU NOTICE
HOW MANY GUARDS THEY HAVE POSTED
AT THE ENTRANCE
TO THE PRISON?
ONLY TWO.
I GUESS THEY ASSUME
THIS PLACE IS SO SECURE
THEY DON'T NEED ANY MORE.
WHY DO YOU ASK?
WE DON'T PLAN TO SIT HERE
WHILE THEY KILL US ONE BY ONE.
WE WERE ABLE
TO GET A MESSAGE THROUGH
TO ANOTHER TRABE VESSEL
BEFORE WE WERE BOARDED.
HELP IS ON THE WAY.
CAN WE COUNT ON YOU?
CAPTAIN'S LOG, SUPPLEMENTAL.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY TO RENDEZVOUS
WITH MR. NEELIX.
I CAN ONLY HOPE
THAT HE HAD MORE LUCK
WITH THE KAZON THAN WE DID.
CAPTAIN, WE'RE APPROACHING
THE COORDINATES.
ALL STOP.
I DON'T SEE ANY TRACE OF HIM.
LONG-RANGE SENSORS INDICATE
NO SIGN OF MR. NEELIX'S SHUTTLE
WITHIN A RADIUS
OF TWO LIGHT YEARS.
THE KAZON HAVE HIM.
WE CANNOT JUMP TO CONCLUSIONS.
HE MAY SIMPLY HAVE BEEN DELAYED.
WE'LL HOLD POSITION HERE
FOR TWO HOURS.
IF HE HASN'T SHOWN UP BY THEN,
WE'LL GO TO SOBRAS.
LIEUTENANT, COULD YOU
FILL US IN A LITTLE?
THERE ARE ALL KINDS OF RUMORS
FLYING AROUND
ABOUT WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THE KAZON.
NOTHING'S GOING ON YET.
THE CAPTAIN'S TALK
WITH SESKA FELL APART
PRETTY QUICKLY.
NOTHING'S GOING
TO COME OF ALL THIS.
B'ELANNA,
YOU WERE SESKA'S FRIEND.
COULDN'T YOU GET WORD TO HER?
TRY TO WORK THINGS OUT.
NO, I COULDN'T.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND...
HOGAN, IT'S GONE TOO FAR.
SESKA ISN'T THE PERSON
WE THOUGHT SHE WAS.
I DON'T TRUST HER ANYMORE.
EVEN IF IT MEANS
US GETTING HOME IN ONE PIECE.
OR DO YOU AGREE
WITH OUR CAPTAIN
THAT HOLDING ON TO OUR
TECHNOLOGY IS WORTH DYING FOR?
WHO ARE YOU TO BE
SECOND-GUESSING
CAPTAIN JANEWAY?
THE HARDEST THING YOU
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT
IS KEEPING THAT
DILITHIUM CHAMBER FILLED.
SHE IS DOING THE BEST
SHE CAN TO GET US HOME.
AND IF YOU DON'T LIKE
THE WAY SHE'S DOING IT
I REALLY DON'T WANT
TO HEAR ABOUT IT.
IS THAT CLEAR?
PERFECTLY.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN
ARE TOO WEAK TO RUN.
WE'LL HAVE
TO CARRY THEM.
WE COULD USE ANOTHER
PAIR OF STRONG ARMS.
YOU CAN COUNT ON ME.
I CAN'T PROMISE
WE'LL GET OUT OF HERE ALIVE,
BUT IF WE STAY HERE,
WE'LL DIE ANYWAY.
I'D RATHER GO OUT
FIGHTING, MYSELF.
THAT ONE
MIGHT BE A PROBLEM.
HE'S THE KIND
THAT'LL START SHOOTING
AT THE FIRST SIGN
OF TROUBLE.
I'LL KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
( distant shouting )
THIS MAY BE IT.
BE READY.
STAY BACK.
GET BACK!
AGAINST THE WALLS.
NOW! LET'S GO, LET'S GO.
COME ON. COME ON, EVERYONE.
LET'S GO. COME ON.
COME ON.
NICE WORK, MY FRIENDS.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT.
WE'RE GOING AFTER HIM.
MR. PARIS, SET A COURSE
FOR SOBRAS, FULL IMPULSE.
TUVOK, ARM THE PHASER BANKS
AND LOAD THE FORWARD
TORPEDO BAYS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE KAZON
HAVE IN STORE FOR US.
SHIELDS AT FULL POWER.
YELLOW ALERT.
ALL HANDS AT THE READY.
CAPTAIN.
WHAT IS IT?
SHIPS.
KAZON SHIPS
ON LONG-RANGE SENSORS.
CLOSING FAST.
CONFIRMED, CAPTAIN.
ON SCREEN.
Tuvok:
IT APPEARS TO BE AN ARMADA,
AND THEIR WEAPONS
ARE POWERED.
RED ALERT.
POWER ALL WEAPONS SYSTEMS
AND STAND READY.
MR. KIM,
HAIL THE LEAD SHIP.
THEY'RE HAILING US, CAPTAIN.
I'LL PUT IT ON SCREEN.
Hello, Captain.
I'd like you to meet
my good friend Mabus.
We've just escaped
from the Kazon Pommar.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
ON A KAZON SHIP?
They're Trabe vessels actually.
Everything the Kazon have,
they stole from the Trabe.
Mabus will tell you
all about it
over a sumptuous dinner.
The food hasn't been
very good
where we've been.
I LOOK FORWARD TO IT.
I WAS 8 YEARS OLD
WHEN IT STARTED.
I WASN'T EVEN
PARTICULARLY AWARE OF THE KAZON.
THEY LIVED
IN RESTRICTED AREAS
THAT CHILDREN
WEREN'T ALLOWED TO GO NEAR.
I DIDN'T KNOW THEY
IN LIVED POVERTY, THE FILTH...
I DIDN'T KNOW THEY WERE
PERSECUTED BY THE TRABE POLICE.
I WAS TOLD THEY WERE VIOLENT
AND DANGEROUS,
AND HAD TO BE KEPT ISOLATED
SO THEY WOULDN'T GET LOOSE
AND KILL US,
WHICH IS EXACTLY
WHAT THEY DID.
BUT WE BROUGHT IT
ON OURSELVES.
THE TRABE TREATED THEM
LIKE ANIMALS--
FENCED THEM IN, ENCOURAGED THEM
TO FIGHT AMONGST THEMSELVES
SO THEY WOULDN'T TURN ON US
AND SAT BY WHILE THEY TURNED
INTO A VIOLENT, ANGRY ARMY.
WHEN THEY FINALLY REALIZED
WE WERE THEIR TRUE ENEMY
WE DIDN'T STAND A CHANCE.
I WAS LUCKIER THAN MOST.
A FRIEND'S FATHER GRABBED ME
AND TOOK ME AND HIS FAMILY
TO ONE OF THE STARSHIPS
THAT MANAGED TO ESCAPE.
I CAN STILL REMEMBER...
IT HAPPENED SO FAST.
ONE MINUTE...
I WAS A HAPPY CHILD
PLAYING IN A FIELD;
THE NEXT, AN ORPHAN,
EXILED IN SPACE.
IT STRIKES ME
THAT IN MANY WAYS, WE'RE
IN THE SAME PREDICAMENT--
SEPARATED FROM THE LIVES
THAT WE KNEW,
SEARCHING FOR HOME.
A GOAL YOU MAY WELL ACHIEVE,
CAPTAIN
BUT THE KAZON HAVE REFUSED
TO ALLOW US TO FIND
A NEW HOME WORLD.
EVERY TIME WE TRY
TO SETTLE SOMEWHERE,
THEY ATTACK AND DRIVE US AWAY.
WE'RE SCATTERED, LIKE NOMADS,
WITH NO HOME AND LITTLE HOPE.
IT HAPPENED
OVER 30 YEARS AGO
AND THE KAZON ARE STILL
TRYING TO PUNISH YOU?
REMARKABLE, ISN'T IT?
MOST OF THE TRABE
WHO PERSECUTED THE KAZON
ARE EITHER DEAD
OR OLD MEN BY NOW.
MOST OF US WERE CHILDREN
WHEN THE UPRISING OCCURRED,
AND OUR CHILDREN ARE INNOCENT.
BUT THE KAZON'S DESIRE FOR
REVENGE IS AS STRONG AS EVER.
How are you able to transmit to
us without your crew knowing it?
THAT'S FOR ME TO WORRY ABOUT.
LET'S JUST SAY I'M VERY FAMILIAR
WITH COMMUNICATIONS PROTOCOLS.
NOW, WILL YOU LET ME
TALK TO SESKA?
Not without some proof
you can be trusted.
SHE AND I KNEW EACH OTHER
FOR A LONG TIME.
SHE KNOWS THAT I CAN BE TRUSTED.
JUST LET ME TALK TO HER.
I will convey your message.
Contact me tomorrow,
and I'll let you know
if she's willing to talk to you.
( sighs )
Neelix:
BEFORE THE UPRISING
THE TRABE WERE KNOWN
AS A HIGHLY-EVOLVED SPECIES.
THEY PRODUCED SCHOLARS
AND ARTISTS WHO WERE
WIDELY ADMIRED
AND THEIR TECHNOLOGY WAS AMONG
THE FINEST IN THE QUADRANT.
NO ONE REALLY KNEW
ABOUT THE KAZON
AND HOW THEY WERE BEING TREATED.
WHY NOT?
HOLDING ANOTHER CULTURE
IN VIRTUAL SLAVERY
ISN'T THE KIND OF THING
THAT WOULD GO UNNOTICED.
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND,
THE TRABE WERE RICH
AND POWERFUL.
THEY MANIPULATED INFORMATION
ABOUT THE CONDITIONS
ON THEIR PLANET,
AND NO ONE WANTED TO RISK
OFFENDING THEM
AND LOSING OPPORTUNITIES
FOR TRADE.
IT SEEMS TO ME THEY'VE
LEARNED THEIR LESSON.
MABUS AND HIS PEOPLE
HAVE FREELY ACKNOWLEDGED
THAT THEY WERE RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM.
Tuvok:
STILL, I DO NOT SEE THAT
IT IS A PARTICULARLY GOOD
IDEA TO FORM AN ALLIANCE
WITH THE BLOOD ENEMIES
OF THE KAZON.
WE RISK UNITING
ALL THE FACTIONS AGAINST US.
THE ONLY THING
THE KAZON AGREE ON NOW
IS THAT WE
ARE THEIR COMMON ENEMY.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE
IT GETTING MUCH WORSE.
THE TRABE HAVE A
LOT OF SHIPS
AND A LOT OF WEAPONS
IN THAT CONVOY.
I THINK THIS ALLIANCE WOULD BE
BETTER THAN NONE AT ALL.
I'D RATHER NOT BE
IN THE POSITION
OF MAKING AN ALLIANCE AT ALL,
BUT THAT MAY BE A LUXURY
WE SIMPLY DON'T HAVE.
MY GUT TELLS ME WE DON'T HAVE
ANY FRIENDS AMONG THE KAZON.
AS FOR THE TRABE, I BELIEVE
THAT PEOPLE HAVE
A CAPACITY TO CHANGE.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
STARFLEET'S POLICY
TO DEAL WITH NEW SPECIES
ON A BASIS OF OPENNESS
AND TRUST...
UNTIL PROVEN OTHERWISE.
CAPTAIN,
I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
I WANTED TO THANK YOU FOR THE
USE OF YOUR MEDICAL FACILITIES.
WE HAVE
VERY FEW DOCTORS.
EVERYONE SEEMS TO BE
IN GENERALLY GOOD CONDITION.
MALNUTRITION
IS THE MOST COMMON PROBLEM
BUT IT'S EASILY ALLEVIATED
WITH BIO-NUTRIENT SUPPLEMENTS.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
HOW MUCH LONGER DO YOU NEED?
I'D SAY LESS THAN AN HOUR.
WILL YOU WALK WITH ME?
OF COURSE.
I'VE BEEN THINKING...
ABOUT OUR CONVERSATION
AT DINNER.
MM-HMM.
ABOUT THE THINGS WE SHARE,
AND IT SEEMS TO ME
WE COULD BE OF MUTUAL
BENEFIT TO EACH OTHER.
GO ON.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
TO THE POSSIBILITY
OF OUR JOINING FORCES--
MY STARSHIP AND YOUR CONVOY.
CLEARLY WE'D BE A STRONGER
FORCE IF WE DID THAT.
WE COULD TRAVEL TOGETHER
FOR AS LONG
AS IT'S ADVANTAGEOUS
TO BOTH OF US.
MAYBE WE'LL FIND OUR WAY
OUT OF KAZON TERRITORY,
AND YOU COULD SETTLE
ON A NEW HOME WORLD.
IT'S A REASONABLE IDEA,
CAPTAIN.
I HAVE NO OBJECTION.
BUT IT WOULD ONLY BENEFIT
YOUR GROUP AND MINE.
THERE ARE OTHER TRABE
WHO WOULDN'T ENJOY
THE SAME PROTECTION.
I WONDER...
IF YOU MIGHT CONSIDER
A SOMEWHAT MORE... BOLD PLAN.
TELL ME.
TOGETHER, THE VOYAGER
AND THE TRABE
WOULD BE A FORCE
TO BE RECKONED WITH.
SUPPOSE WE TOOK
ADVANTAGE OF THAT
AND ASKED
THE REPRESENTATIVES
OF ALL THE KAZON FACTIONS
TO JOIN US
AT THE BARGAINING TABLE.
IN ORDER TO ACHIEVE WHAT?
PEACE. TOGETHER
WE WOULD REPRESENT
A STABILIZING FORCE
IN THIS PART
OF THE QUADRANT--
BRING THE FACTIONS TOGETHER.
CONVINCE THEM THAT
AN END TO VIOLENCE
WOULD BE IN EVERYONE'S
BEST INTEREST.
THINK ABOUT IT.
I BELIEVE IT COULD WORK.
IT'S A MESSAGE FROM VOYAGER.
THEY'VE FORMED AN ALLIANCE...
WITH THE TRABE!
THE TRABE?
THEY'RE CALLING FOR A CONFERENCE
OF ALL FIRST MAJES.
HOW COULD THIS
HAVE HAPPENED?
IT HAPPENED BECAUSE
YOU LET VOYAGER SLIP AWAY
RIGHT INTO THE HANDS
OF THE TRABE BY INSISTING
ON THAT RIDICULOUS
EXCHANGE OF CREWS.
I COULD NOT LET
THE NEGOTIATIONS
BE DICTATED BY THAT WOMAN.
THAT'S BECOMING
A TIRED REFRAIN, CULLAH.
ONE DAY THAT ATTITUDE
WILL BE YOUR UNDOING.
WATCH YOUR TONGUE.
OR WHAT?
I'M CARRYING YOUR CHILD.
I DON'T THINK YOU'D DO ANYTHING
TO JEOPARDIZE HIM.
WE CAN STILL TURN THIS
TO OUR ADVANTAGE.
WE HAVE A CREWMAN ON VOYAGER
WHO'S WILLING TO PROVIDE
INFORMATION TO US.
THERE'S LONG-TERM POTENTIAL
IN THAT ARRANGEMENT.
WE MUSTN'T LOSE SIGHT OF IT.
YOU'RE NOT SUGGESTING
WE GO TO THIS CONFERENCE--
THAT WE COME RUNNING
LIKE A CALOGAN DOG
WHEN THE FEDERATIONS
CALL?
COULD YOU RISK BEING THE ONLY
MAJE WHO DOESN'T ATTEND?
OF COURSE YOU'LL GO,
AND LISTEN.
NOTHING SHOULD BE
NEGOTIATED THERE--
NOT AT THE POINT
OF A FEDERATION WEAPON
BUT YOU CAN LEARN A GREAT DEAL.
ASSESS THE MOOD
OF THE OTHER MAJES.
FIND OUT THE STRENGTH
OF THE TRABE CONVOY.
YOU MAY BE RIGHT.
YOU CAN COME OUT
OF THIS A HERO.
YOU CAN USE
THIS CONFERENCE
TO UNITE THE FACTIONS
ERADICATE THE TRABE
ONCE AND FOR ALL
AND TAKE VOYAGER
AS A TROPHY.
OOH.
CAPTAIN'S LOG,
STARDATE 49342.5.
NEELIX HAS RETURNED
FROM SOBRAS, WHERE HE LEARNED
A DISTURBING PIECE
OF INFORMATION
THAT MAY REQUIRE US
TO RETHINK OUR PLANS.
HE WAS A TAKRIT--
A BAND OF MERCENARIES
THAT OPERATES IN THIS SYSTEM.
WHAT WAS HE DOING WHEN THE
KAZON-POMMAR ARRESTED HIM?
MY CONTACT ON THE PLANET SAID
THAT HE WAS MAKING A SKETCH
OF THE CONFERENCE SITE.
AND, BELIEVE ME,
THE TAKRIT ARE NOT KNOWN
FOR THEIR ART.
WHO SENT HIM?
THAT'S AS MUCH INFORMATION
AS I GOT.
SO SOMEONE WANTS TO
SABOTAGE THIS CONFERENCE.
Chakotay:
ONE OF THE MAJES.
WHY MISS A CHANCE
TO WIPE OUT YOUR RIVALS
WHILE THEY'RE TOGETHER
IN ONE ROOM?
IF THAT IS TRUE, THEN
ONE OF THEM WILL
UNDOUBTEDLY TRY TO LEAVE
BEFORE THE MEETING
IS FINISHED.
CAPTAIN, I THINK YOU SHOULD
CONSIDER NOT GOING
TO THE CONFERENCE.
NO. IF I CAN HELP BRING
STABILITY TO THIS QUADRANT,
I'M NOT GOING TO WALK AWAY
BECAUSE OF A RUMOR.
A RUMOR THAT MUST
BE TAKEN SERIOUSLY NONETHELESS.
AGREED.
COMMANDER...
MONITOR ALL THE KAZON VESSELS
CAREFULLY
AND LOOK OUT FOR ANY
SUSPICIOUS SHIP MOVEMENT
NEAR THE SURFACE.
KEEP US ON A CONSTANT
TRANSPORTER LOCK
SO WE CAN BEAM OUT
AT THE FIRST HINT OF TROUBLE.
TUVOK, NEELIX,
YOU'RE WITH ME.
I GAVE A GREAT DEAL
OF THOUGHT
TO THE SHAPE
OF THE TABLE.
I FINALLY DECIDED
ON A TRIANGLE.
YOUR GROUP WOULD
SIT ON ONE SIDE.
THE MAJES WOULD
OCCUPY THE OTHER TWO.
DOES THAT SEEM
APPROPRIATE?
HAVE YOU HEARD
ANYTHING MORE
ABOUT THE MATTER
WE DISCUSSED?
DON'T TALK
ABOUT THAT HERE.
IT COULD MEAN MY HEAD.
DOES THE TABLE SHAPE
SEEM ACCEPTABLE?
TERSA, THIS TIME I AM HERE
WITH A POWERFUL STARSHIP.
YOU'D BETTER BE TELLING ME
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW.
I AM, I SWEAR.
I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR MAKING IT POSSIBLE
TO HAVE THE CONFERENCE
HERE ON SOBRAS.
MY MAJE HAS
REWARDED ME HANDSOMELY
FOR THE PRESTIGE
IT AFFORDS HIM.
IF THERE IS ANY FURTHER WAY
I CAN BE OF SERVICE
PLEASE LET ME KNOW.
HE HASN'T HEARD ANYTHING MORE,
BUT HE'S FRIGHTENED.
HE MUST BELIEVE
SOMETHING'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
Tersa:
THE FIRST MAJES
OF THE KAZON ORDER.
MINNIS OF THE POMMAR...
SURAT OF THE MOSTRAL...
LORAN OF THE HOBII...
VALEK OF THE OGLAMAR...
AND CULLAH OF THE NISTRIM.
CAPTAIN, WE SEEM DESTINED
TO ENCOUNTER EACH OTHER.
THIS IS MABUS,
A GOVERNOR OF
THE TRABE.
MAJE CULLAH, I'M GRATIFIED
TO BE MEETING YOU LIKE THIS.
I HOPE WE'LL BE ABLE
TO COME TO TERMS.
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D SEE THE DAY
WHEN ANY OF US WOULD SIT
AT A TABLE WITH THE TRABE.
TIMES CHANGE, MAJE.
PERHAPS.
SHALL WE?
OUR GRACIOUS HOST, JAL MINNIS
HAS PROVIDED FOOD AND DRINK
TO MAKE OUR DISCUSSIONS
MORE PLEASANT.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR COMING.
WE HOPE THIS WILL LEAD
TO A NEW CLIMATE OF PEACE.
PEACE?
WITH THE TRABE?
FORGIVE ME
IF I'M A BIT SKEPTICAL.
I UNDERSTAND.
AFTER DECADES OF ANTAGONISM,
YOU'RE BOUND
TO BE SUSPICIOUS.
BUT SURELY, EVERYONE HERE IS
TIRED OF CONSTANT VIOLENCE.
AREN'T YOU REALLY TRYING
TO GET US TO RELAX OUR GUARD
SO THE TRABE
CAN CONQUER US AGAIN?
HOW COULD WE DO THAT?
WE'RE SCATTERED AND DISPIRIT.
ALL WE ASK FOR IS A CHANCE
TO FIND A NEW HOME WORLD
AND SETTLE PEACEFULLY.
EXCUSE ME.
CAPTAIN JANEWAY,
I'M CURIOUS AS TO THE NATURE
OF THIS ALLIANCE
YOU'VE STRUCK WITH THE TRABE...
ESPECIALLY SINCE YOU REFUSED
MY OFFER OF A SIMILAR PACT.
Janeway:
I FOUND THE GOALS
OF THE TRABE
TO BE COMPATIBLE
WITH OUR OWN.
I REPRESENT AN ORGANIZATION
WHICH IS DEVOTED
TO PEACEFUL COEXISTENCE
AMONG PEOPLE.
THE TRABE WANT
NOTHING MORE THAN THAT.
THE TRABE HAVE ALWAYS
WANTED PEACE FOR THEMSELVES.
BUT WE PAID THE PRICE.
THEY LIVED IN LUXURY
AND WE LIVED
IN SQUALOR AND MISERY.
WHAT I FEAR, CAPTAIN,
IS THAT THIS UNION
YOU'VE MADE WITH THE TRABE
IS AN EFFORT TO FORCE US
TO CAPITULATE.
IF SO, WE ASSURE YOU
IT IS DOOMED TO FAILURE.
I WON'T PRETEND THAT OUR
ALLIANCE WASN'T AN ATTEMPT
TO MAKE A SHOW OF STRENGTH.
SEPARATELY, WE AND
THE TRABE ARE VULNERABLE.
TOGETHER, WE ARE STRONGER.
ARE YOU THREATENING US,
CAPTAIN?
IT IS IMPORTANT THAT YOU
UNDERSTAND OUR DETERMINATION.
BUT IT'S NOT A THREAT.
IT'S AN OFFER.
A NEGOTIATED PEACE
AMONG ALL OF US WOULD
PROVIDE A GREATER STABILITY
IN THIS QUADRANT.
HOW COULD THAT DO ANYTHING
BUT BENEFIT US ALL?
I CAN'T SPEAK
FOR ALL OF YOU,
BUT I FOR ONE DON'T THINK
WE CAN TRUST THIS PROPOSAL.
A WOMAN AND A TRABE--
HOW CAN WE LISTEN
TO THEM?
I FIND YOU NOTHING
BUT A HYPOCRITE, CAPTAIN--
ALLYING YOURSELF
TO THE GREATEST VILLAINS
THIS QUADRANT
HAS EVER KNOWN.
IF THIS IS WHERE YOUR REVERED
FEDERATION VALUES HAVE TAKEN YOU
I WANT NO PART OF IT.
GENTLEMEN,
ALLOW ME TO CONFER WITH
MY FEDERATION COLLEAGUES.
PLEASE, HAVE
SOME REFRESHMENTS
AND LET US CONTINUE
IN A FEW MOMENTS.
CAPTAIN,
WOULD YOU PLEASE JOIN ME?
( rumbling )
CAPTAIN, I REALLY NEED
TO TALK TO YOU NOW.
GET DOWN!
WHAT IS THIS, CAPTAIN?
Janeway:
IT'S A TRAP! TAKE COVER!
VOYAGER, RED ALERT.
Chakotay:
We're on it.
YOU'VE RUINED WHAT
WOULD HAVE BEEN
THE GREATEST STEP
TOWARD PEACE IN DECADES.
PEACE? A MASSACRE?
I COULD HAVE DECIMATED
THE KAZON LEADERSHIP.
IT WOULD HAVE TAKEN THEM
YEARS TO RECOVER.
YOU PLANNED THIS WHOLE THING,
AND USED OUR GOOD WILL TO MAKE
SURE YOU WERE SUCCESSFUL.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE KAZON.
THERE'S NO DEALING
WITH THEM.
VIOLENCE IS ALL
THEY UNDERSTAND.
OR PERHAPS
IT'S ALL YOU UNDERSTAND.
YOU ARE NAIVE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S CLEAR
YOU HAVE NO UNDERSTANDING
OF THE HARSH REALITIES
OF THIS PART OF SPACE.
WHAT I TRIED TO DO WAS
DONE AS MUCH FOR YOU
AS IT WAS FOR US.
I'M NOT GRATEFUL,
AND I WANT YOU OFF MY SHIP.
CHIEF, BEAM OUR FORMER GUEST
BACK TO HIS VESSEL.
CAPTAIN, DON'T DO THIS.
YOU'RE GOING TO NEED US.
I DON'T THINK SO.
THE KAZON WILL BE DETERMINED
TO SEEK REVENGE.
HOW CAN THIS ONE SHIP
HOPE TO SURVIVE?
NOT BY MAKING DEALS
WITH EXECUTIONERS.
ENERGIZE.
I WOULD SUGGEST WE
DEPART BEFORE THE KAZON
HAVE A CHANCE TO RETURN
TO THEIR SHIPS.
JANEWAY TO PARIS.
GET US OUT OF HERE.
THERE'S NO QUESTION WE'RE MORE
VULNERABLE NOW THAN EVER.
WE HAVE TO TAKE EVERY MEASURE
TO MAKE SURE WE'RE
PREPARED FOR AN ATTACK.
I WANT CONTINUAL
DIAGNOSTICS ON
ALL SHIPS' SYSTEMS.
I WILL SCHEDULE ADDITIONAL
BATTLE DRILLS FOR ALL HANDS.
MR. NEELIX,
WHAT ABOUT OUR FOOD SUPPLIES?
WE'RE IN GOOD SHAPE, CAPTAIN.
WE SHOULDN'T HAVE TO STOP
ANYWHERE FOR SEVERAL WEEKS.
GOOD. LIEUTENANT,
WHAT'S THE CONDITION
OF OUR
PROPULSION SYSTEMS?
WE HAVE A REASONABLE
SUPPLY OF ANTIMATTER.
BARRING ANY MAJOR PROBLEMS,
WE SHOULD HAVE
MAXIMUM PERFORMANCE
OF BOTH WARP AND
IMPULSE ENGINES.
THERE'S JUST ONE MORE THING
I WANT TO SAY.
I HOPE THERE'S A LESSON
FOR ALL OF US IN THIS.
ALTHOUGH SOME OF THE SPECIES
WE'VE ENCOUNTERED HERE
HAVE BEEN PEACEFUL,
OTHERS SEEM GOVERNED ONLY
BY THEIR OWN SELF-INTERESTS.
THIS APPEARS TO BE
A REGION OF SPACE THAT
DOESN'T HAVE MANY RULES.
BUT I BELIEVE WE CAN LEARN
SOMETHING FROM THE EVENTS
THAT HAVE UNFOLDED.
IN A PART OF SPACE
WHERE THERE ARE FEW RULES
IT'S MORE IMPORTANT THAN EVER
THAT WE HOLD FAST TO OUR OWN.
IN A REGION WHERE SHIFTING
ALLEGIANCES ARE COMMONPLACE,
WE HAVE TO HAVE SOMETHING
STABLE TO RELY ON, AND WE DO--
THE PRINCIPALS AND THE IDEALS
OF THE FEDERATION.
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
THOSE ARE THE BEST ALLIES
WE COULD HAVE.