Warp 5...
Warp 6...
Warp 7.
I've reached
critical velocity.
B'ELANNA:
Okay, everything
looks good on this end.
Fire up
the new engines.
Acknowledged.
Engaging transwarp drive
in four...
three...two...
( beeping )
( rumbling )
Transwarp online!
Warp 9.2...
9.3...
My vector's
drifting.
KIM:
Try to stabilize
your field symmetry.
Got it.
Warp 9.6...
9.7...
( alarm beeping )
I'm reading a fracture
in the port nacelle pylon.
B'ELANNA:
Full power
to structural integrity.
Warp 9.9...
9.95...
I'm approaching
the threshold.
( grunts )
But the nacelle
isn't holding.
KIM:
Tie in auxiliary power.
It's no use.
I'm breaking up! I'm breaking---
( yells )
( dramatic theme plays )
You're dead.
( sighs )
( triumphant theme playing )
( dramatic theme playing )
It's the
pylon again.
Every time we get close
to crossing the threshold,
the subspace torque rips
a nacelle off the shuttle.
What about
a duranium alloy?
We could try using
it to reinforce--
I thought about that already.
It's too brittle.
More coffee?
Ah,
you look like a happy bunch.
We've hit a wall.
Oh. Well, maybe I can help.
Great. Do you know anything
about quantum warp theory
or multispectral subspace
engine design?
No,
but I'm a quick study.
( clears throat )
What are we working on?
Do you have anything to eat?
Sure.
There's some Kalavian biscuits
somewhere in the kitchen.
I guess
I'll go find them myself.
Fill him in.
KIM:
Neelix...
It would take
too long to--
What are you saying?
I'm not smart enough?
I'll have you know
I did two years
as an engineer's assistant
aboard a Trabalian freighter.
I'm well-versed
in warp theory.
Okay, okay,
we'll tell you.
We're trying to break
the maximum warp barrier.
Nothing in the universe
can go warp 10.
It's a theoretical
impossibility.
In principle,
if you were ever
to reach warp 10, you'd be
traveling at infinite velocity.
Infinite velocity.
Got it.
So, tha-that means very fast.
It means that
you would occupy
every point in
the universe simultaneously.
In theory, you could go
any place in the wink of an eye.
Time and distance
would have no meaning.
If Voyager achieved
warp 10,
we could be home in as long
as it takes to push a button.
Wow!
And you're working
on this?
We discovered
a new form of dilithium
in the asteroid field
we surveyed last month.
It remains stable at
a much higher warp frequency.
The problem is,
every time
we simulate crossing
the transwarp threshold,
the nacelles get
torn off the ship.
I remember there was a time when
I lost a warp nacelle
going through
a dark matter nebula.
This is
a very different problem.
I realize that.
I'm just using it as an example.
As the ship went
through the nebula,
it sent out
a dark matter bow wave.
Eventually,
so much pressure built up,
it tore the nacelle
from its housing.
Now, maybe the same thing
is happening to you.
The simulations
don't indicate
any kind of subspace stress
on the nacelles.
PARIS:
Wait a minute.
What about
the shuttle itself?
What do you mean?
Maybe we've been looking
in the wrong place.
What if the nacelles
aren't being torn from the ship?
What if the ship is being torn
from the nacelles?
The hull of the shuttle
is made of tritanium alloy.
At the speeds
we're talking about,
that alloy
could depolarize...
And create
a velocity differential.
The fuselage
would be traveling
at a faster rate of speed
than the nacelles.
That means
we just have to set up
a depolarization matrix
around the fuselage.
That's it!
Neelix,
you're a genius.
( chuckling )
I have no idea
what they just said.
Warp 9.92.
The pylons
are secure.
Everything
looks good.
9.97...
8...
9...
( whooshing )
( sighs )
Warp 10.
B'ELANNA:
You've crossed the threshold.
You've done it! And there's
been no damage to the nacelles.
When you came to me
a month ago
and said
you had a way
to cross
the transwarp threshold,
I thought it was more
of a fantasy than a theory.
Congratulations
to all of you.
So we can try
a manned test flight?
What's your flight plan?
I'll bring the shuttle
up to speed.
The second
I cross the threshold,
I'll cut the engines,
drop out of warp and come about.
After that, we'll analyze
the shuttle's sensor logs.
Once we know it's safe
to travel at transwarp,
we'll try
a more extended flight.
To be honest,
it's almost frightening.
Up till now,
it's all been theory.
I never thought
it would actually happen.
Are we ready for it?
In the last couple
of centuries,
we've always managed to use
new technologies wisely.
I'm confident
this time won't
be any different.
Besides, there's no way to put
the genie back in the bottle.
All we can do now is keep
moving forward...
carefully.
Well, good luck,
Mr. Paris.
If this works, you'll be joining
an elite group of pilots.
Orville Wright, Neil Armstrong,
Zefram Cochrane...
And Tom Paris.
I kind of like
the way that sounds.
I thought you might.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door chimes )
Come in.
( door opens )
Oh. Captain!
I, um...
At ease, Mr. Paris.
I know it's late.
( sighs )
( clears throat )
Can I...
Get you anything?
No, thank you.
Now,
why do I get the feeling
this isn't
just a social call?
I've just spoken to
the doctor...
and it's his opinion
that we let Ensign Kim make
the test flight.
( scoffs softly )
May I ask why?
He checked over
your biometric readings
from the
shuttle simulations.
He says you
have a slight
enzymatic imbalance
in your cerebellum.
So?
I know it doesn't sound
like much,
but he can't predict
what'll happen
when you cross
the threshold.
He believes there's
a small chance
that you could suffer
a brain hemorrhage
under the
subspace stress.
How big a chance?
Two percent.
( scoffs )
Two percent?
( sighs )
I'll take that chance.
There's no reason to.
Ensign Kim is capable
of piloting the shuttle
for this mission.
Yeah, he's capable.
That's not the point.
What is the point,
Mr. Paris?
Well, it's hard to explain,
but...
this is my flight.
Your flight.
When I was a boy,
my father used to tell me
that I was special,
that one day
I'd do something significant.
My teachers at school,
all the kids,
everyone used to say,
"Tom Paris is gonna
do something important
when he grows up."
( sighs )
Obviously,
that didn't happen.
This isn't about
personal redemption.
We're talking
about medical risk.
Your life could be in danger,
and we need you.
Captain, this is the first time
in 10 years
I feel I have a life
to risk.
You're sure about this.
Captain, I've never been so sure
about anything.
Please.
Please,
let me make the flight.
Good luck, Lieutenant.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
Torres to Bridge.
The prelaunch sequence
is complete, Captain.
Acknowledged.
Ensign Kim,
depressurize the shuttle bay
and open
the space doors.
KIM:
Aye, Captain.
Bridge to
Shuttlecraft Cochrane.
You're cleared
for launch.
PARIS:
Aye, Captain.
See you at warp 10.
( dramatic theme playing )
Cochrane to Voyager.
All systems are nominal.
I'm increasing speed.
JANEWAY:
We'll keep up with you
as long as we can.
( chuckles )
( console beeps )
Warp 7,
warp 8...
How's his dilithium matrix
holding up?
There's a slight variance
in the warp field,
but nothing
to worry about.
Torres to
Shuttlecraft Cochrane.
You're clear
for transwarp velocity.
Acknowledged.
Engaging transwarp drive
in four...
three...
two...
PARIS:
Warp 9.7...
9.8...
( muddled ):
9.9...
He is exceeding
our maximum velocity.
I am switching
to long-range sensors.
PARIS:
Warp 9.95!
TUVOK:
He is approaching
the threshold.
Engine output at maximum.
Velocity...
Warp 10.
Yes!
PARIS:
Transwarp engines are stable.
So are the nacelle pylons.
I'm going to--
( voice distorting ):
Oh, my God....
( distortion increases ):
Oh, my...
Lieutenant,
can you hear me?
( console beeping )
KIM: Captain, he just...
Just disappeared
off sensors.
Increase sensor gain
to maximum.
Nothing.
I can't find him.
He's gone.
( dramatic theme continues )
I've done
three full sensor sweeps.
No sign of the shuttle
within five parsecs.
Tuvok, could the shuttle
have been destroyed?
I don't
believe so.
Sensors indicate that he did
cross the warp threshold.
If that's true, then he could be
anywhere in the universe.
We'll just have to keep
searching our small corner.
Run a multispectral sweep.
I want to see if--
TUVOK:
Captain,
there's a quantum surge
off the port bow.
Something is coming
out of subspace.
Janeway to Paris.
KIM: He's alive,
but his life signs
are weak.
Bridge to
Transporter Room 2.
Beam Mr. Paris
directly to Sickbay.
Commander, bring
the shuttle aboard.
I'll be
in Sickbay.
Aye, Captain.
DOCTOR:
His life signs
are normal.
A few elevated
serotonin readings
in the hypothalamus.
From what I can tell,
he's just...
asleep.
Can you wake him?
I don't see why not.
Wake up, Lieutenant!
( gasping )
( sighs )
Are you all right, Tom?
I'm back.
We tracked you until you
crossed the threshold.
Then you disappeared
from our sensors.
Do you remember
what happened?
Oh, yeah.
I was...
I was staring at
the velocity indicator.
It said warp 10.
And then,
as I watched it,
I suddenly realized
that I was...
watching myself
as well.
I could see the outside
of the shuttle.
I could see Voyager.
I could see
inside Voyager.
inside this room.
For a moment...
I was everywhere.
I mean,
everywhere, Captain.
With the Kazon...
Back home, with the Klingons,
other galaxies,
it was all there.
I don't know how else
to explain it.
It was like...
Well, no,
it wasn't like anything.
DOCTOR:
Well...
I'm glad
you had a good time.
How did you get back
to Voyager?
I saw that you
were looking for me,
so I took the new engines
off-line
and ended up
back where I started.
But...
Oh, it's starting
to slip away.
It all was so vivid,
and now...
B'ELANNA:
Tom!
Oh, I'm fine.
How's the shuttle?
You brought it back
without a scratch.
The onboard sensors
confirm that you did it.
You made it
to warp 10.
JANEWAY:
Congratulations,
Mr. Paris.
You just made
the history books.
We should download
the shuttle's
sensor logs,
analyze the telemetry
they picked up during the flight
before we make another attempt.
You're not
going anywhere,
at least not
for a few hours.
I have some tests I'd like
to run on your majesty
before I release
you back
into the realm
of ordinary humans.
You may...proceed.
We'll download
the logs.
I'll let you know
what we find.
( dramatic theme playing )
Janeway to Kim.
We're ready.
Acknowledged.
I'm downloading the logs into
the Engineering computer core.
( console beeping)
This data describes,
literally,
every cubic centimeter
in this sector.
It's over 5 billion
gigiquads of information.
It would appear that the theory
of infinite velocity is correct.
It may be possible to occupy
every point in the universe
simultaneously.
B'ELANNA:
Then, it's just a matter of
navigation. If we could figure
out how to come out of
transwarp at a specific point...
...this could get us home.
Oh, it could do more
than that.
It could change the very nature
of our existence.
Think of it.
There would be nothing
beyond our reach.
This telemetry is giving us an
invaluable record of the sector.
We can use it
to make a star chart.
Transfer the shuttle logs
to Stellar Cartography
for analysis.
Right.
This is
a new blend.
I'm calling it
Paris Delight.
( chuckles )
It's in honor
of you.
What?
Oh!
Oh, thanks.
That's
very flattering.
I can tell.
Well, you might as well get used
to it. You're a hero now.
Heh, I wish I could say
it was nothing.
Oh!
Oh, I wish Neelix
would name something after me
that tasted a little better.
It smells okay.
No. Trust me.
You're taking your life
into your hands.
So I think the next step
is to try to duplicate
the first shuttle flight,
verify our results.
I agree.
We have to confirm
that none of this was a fluke.
But I do think
that we should increase
the shuttle's memory core
by at least...
( beeping )
What? What's wrong?
( exhaling )
I don't think that coffee
is settling too well.
You wanna go back
to Sickbay?
No, no. I've seen enough
of the doctor for one day.
( groaning )
Oh...
On second thought,
maybe I should--
( groaning )
Torres to Transporter Room 2.
Medical emergency.
Beam Lieutenant Paris
directly to Sickbay.
MAN:
I can't lock onto him.
His pattern keeps changing.
Torres to Sickbay.
We need a medical team
in the mess hall right away.
Hang on,
Tom.
( gasping )
Hmm.
It looks like he's having
an allergic reaction.
What did
he ingest?
Just a cup
of Neelix's coffee.
It's a miracle
he's still alive.
( beeping )
This is strange.
What is?
He's definitely having
an allergic reaction...
to the water
in the coffee.
He's allergic to water?
I don't know
how this is possible, but...
It appears that his entire
biochemistry is changing.
His electrolytes
are breaking down,
interstitial fluids
are congealing.
( gasping acutely )
( gasping continues )
( dramatic theme playing )
The alveoli in his lungs
are mutating.
He's no longer
processing oxygen.
What should we do?
Stand back.
Computer, erect
an isolation field
around
the surgical bay.
Computer, remove all the air
from within the force field
and replace it with
80 percent nitrogen
and 20 percent
acidichloride.
( gasping )
( normal breathing )
He can breathe...
for now.
What's happening
to him?
I have no idea,
but I assume it had
something to do
with his experience
on the shuttle.
( Paris screaming )
( console beeping )
( Paris gasping )
(beeping )
His cellular membranes
are deteriorating.
He's dying.
I need to know more about
what happened on that shuttle,
and I need
to know it now.
Radiation levels, unexplained
anomalies, anything.
You're losing me,
aren't you?
I'm gonna die.
You're too stubborn to die,
Mr. Paris.
I want to try high-saturation
radiometric therapy.
It might slow down
his cellular mutation.
PARIS:
Here lies
Thomas Eugene Paris,
beloved mutant.
A fitting
epitaph,
but I don't intend to
let you use it just yet.
Radiometric emitters
are charged and ready.
Begin with 45 rads per second.
Great. Now it'll read
beloved radioactive mutant.
No effect. Increase the dosage
to 85 rads per second.
I'm going to try inhibiting
the cell mitosis with
a bio-suppressor field.
A big funeral,
with lots of pretty girls
all crying...
Except Torres.
Torres doesn't cry.
Do you ever notice that?
I don't trust people
who don't cry.
Of course,
my father...
he'd say crying
is a sign of weakness.
I never believed that.
Do you cry?
It's not in my program.
Shame.
Heh, you know, it's funny.
What I remember most
about being a kid
are the times I spent
in my room crying.
I liked my room, though.
It was quiet in there.
People'd leave me alone.
I'd keep the door locked.
Read, play games.
Heh, I lost my virginity
in that room.
Seventeen.
Parents were away
for the weekend.
I'll note that
in your medical file.
( groaning softly )
( instrument beeps sharply )
His lymphatic system
is collapsing.
Increase dosage to 98 rads
per second.
Pepperoni!
God, I'd love
a pepperoni pizza
with Kavarian olives right now.
I'm starving!
His life signs are critical.
Maximum dosage.
Oh... Kiss me.
What?
Not you. Her.
She can't breathe
the atmosphere in here.
Consider it a last request.
Sorry, Tom. If we let down the
force field, you'll suffocate.
Oh, what's the difference?
I'm dying anyway.
Do me a favor.
When I'm gone...
call
Starfleet Headquarters...
And tell Dad that I did it.
Tell him...
( instrument beeping sharply )
Prepare to activate
the neural simulator.
KES:
Ready.
Now.
( gasping )
Again.
Again!
( dramatic theme playing )
( instrument sounds
steady tone )
No neural activity.
We can try to revive him.
His cell membranes
have degraded.
There's nothing more
we can do.
Computer...
( beeps )
Remove the acidichloride gas
from the isolation field...
( beeps )
And deactivate the field.
( dramatic theme continues )
It will be necessary
for us to perform an autopsy
on the Lieutenant's body
in the morning.
Until then, I...
suggest you get
some rest.
( dramatic theme continues )
( creaking )
( creaking continues )
( breathing heavily )
You're alive.
( panting )
Wha--
What's happening?
All of your internal organs
are functioning again.
In fact...
You seem to have
an extra one.
What?
You have...two hearts.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( beeping )
I have
30 seconds before
Security picks up
this transmission.
I'm sending you
all current information
on the warp 10
shuttle flight.
Warp 10?
That's impossible.
Not anymore.
Lieutenant Paris crossed
the threshold this morning.
He survived?
In a manner of speaking.
It's all in the file.
This should prove my worth
to you, Rettik.
We'll see.
( beeps )
( sighs )
DOCTOR:
His body is going
through some sort
of mutation.
His DNA
is rewriting itself.
To what end,
I don't know.
Does this have
anything to do
with the enzymatic
imbalance you found?
No.
Can you stop it?
So far,
nothing has worked.
The mutations are
unlike anything
in Starfleet
medical records.
His internal organs
are being rearranged.
Some have atrophied
and been absorbed
into his body.
And there are at least
three others that have appeared
and have no identifiable
function at all.
What about his brain?
There are neuro-electrical
transmutations at work.
His synaptic patterns are
changing...almost every second.
But he does still
recognize me...
the ship.
He knows who he is.
Can I talk to him?
Of course.
But I feel I
should caution you
that while he
still is Tom Paris,
he's becoming something
else as well.
His personality is
erratic, unpredictable.
There are moments
of lucidity
interspersed
with almost...
deranged behavior.
I'll keep it
in mind.
( beeping )
Pretty disgusting,
huh?
You've looked better.
How do you feel?
Like a lab experiment
gone wrong.
Well, we're trying to put
that experiment right.
The doctor's working on a way
to restore your DNA to its--
Why?
Excuse me?
What I'm becoming will probably
be better than who I was.
Lieutenant,
you know that's not true.
Oh, yes, it is.
Admit it.
Part of you will be glad
to see me gone.
I'm the Maquis traitor
who sits on your Bridge
and insults your uniform,
remember?
We're all concerned
about you, Tom.
We're here to help you.
No, you're not.
You're trying to take this
away from me.
Take what away from you?
What I'm becoming.
How do you know
this isn't good for me?
this isn't
the best thing that's ever
happened to me?
That's a possibility,
and then again,
it could kill you.
We need to find out
what's going on.
( scoffs )
You're lying...
Just like him...
Just like everyone
around here,
always lying,
always telling me that I'm
doing a good job,
that you're glad
I'm on the ship,
but none of that's true.
Why can't you
just say it?
You're jealous that I broke
the transwarp barrier
and now you're hoping
I'll die!
You're right, doctor.
I don't think there's
anything I can do here.
Wait, Captain.
I'm sorry.
Please come back.
I know you're doing
what you can. It's just...
I'm scared.
I didn't mean
to lash out at you.
What you're going through
would scare any of us,
but you have to hang on,
Tom.
We're doing everything we can
to help you.
I know you are.
And I know you'll fail!
( groans )
( dramatic theme playing )
( panting )
You know...
I used to look up to you,
but now you seem so small,
so insignificant.
You don't even know what--
What-- What--
( choking )
( Paris panting )
( chuckles softly )
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
Doctor?
The rate
of genetic mutation
has accelerated
by 12 percent.
I want you to run
a nucleogenic scan
to determine how much of his
original DNA is left intact.
In the meantime, I'm going to
see about treating him with--
PARIS:
Doctor!
( sighs )
What is it now,
Mr. Paris?
( lisping ):
I need to talk.
So I've noticed.
Is it urgent?
I'm rather busy
right now.
Urgent.
Yes, urgent.
Let...
me out of here.
I'm afraid
that's not possible.
Please.
I can't stay here.
I have to get off this ship.
Leave Voyager?
Why?
( sighs )
I...
understand.
It's all so clear now.
What do
you understand?
The present...
The past...
They're both
in the future.
The future
is in the past.
I beg your pardon?
Listen to me!
I am more...
I'm everything.
Let me go.
Go where,
Tom?
I can't...
( panting )
Please?
Please!
Something tells me
we'd better hurry.
I believe the answer lies
in forcing his DNA
to revert to
its original coding.
Once that occurs,
his body should return
to its former state.
How do we do that?
We destroy all of the new DNA
in his body.
His cells will have to use the
original coding as a blueprint.
But the only way
to destroy the mutant DNA
is with highly focused
antiproton radiation.
antiprotons?
The only place on this ship
which generates antiprotons
is the warp core.
Exactly.
I'd like to place Mr. Paris
in an isotropic restraint
and then infuse it
with controlled antiproton
bursts. A tricky venture,
but I see
no other alternative.
We'll have to take
the warp core off-line.
Then I'll need about three hours
to set up an interface.
In three hours,
there won't be
anything left
of Mr. Paris to save.
We have to make the attempt
within an hour, at the most.
Get moving.
( dramatic theme playing )
( panting )
DOCTOR:
What's your status,
Lieutenant?
The interface
is charged and ready.
Infuse him with a two second
antiproton burst.
Take the warp engines
off-line.
( whooshing of engine )
Bleed off
.057 AMUs
of antiproton
radiation.
Shunt it through
the interface.
Transfer
underway.
( rattling )
Doctor, the mutated DNA
in his liver cells
has begun
to deteriorate,
but the original coding
isn't taking over.
I don't understand.
This should be working.
We'll have to increase
the duration of the bursts.
Lieutenant,
prepare a five second burst.
Also, you'll need
to begin depolarizing--
( crashing )
My God.
DOCTOR:
Lieutenant?
WOMAN: Call Security!
( loud crashing )
Lieutenant,
what's happening?
MAN 1:
I got it right now!
( yelling )
MAN 2:
Shut it all down.
( dramatic theme playing )
( static buzzing )
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK:
This is a level 3
security alert.
All hands report
to duty stations.
( alarm blaring )
Janeway to Bridge.
Report.
CHAKOTAY:
Paris broke out of confinement
in Engineering.
He used a phaser
on the port plasma conduit.
We have power failures
all over the ship.
JANEWAY:
Where is he now?
We're having trouble
tracking him.
We can't get power
to the internal sensors.
Tuvok has security teams
searching deck by deck.
I'm on my way
to the Bridge.
( door beeps )
( heavy breathing )
( yells )
( grunts )
Oh, oh...
Phaser discharge
on Deck 6.
Localize it.
KIM:
I'm still having trouble
with internal sensors.
It came from somewhere
between Sections 21
and 27-Alpha.
Tuvok doesn't have
any security in that area.
Chakotay
to Tuvok.
We think Paris
may be on Deck 6.
Deploy security
to Sections 21 through 27-Alpha.
( dramatic theme playing )
Commander, someone's
depressurizing Shuttle Bay 2.
What?
KIM:
There's a launch
in progress.
Tractor beam.
It's off-line.
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK: Tuvok to Bridge.
We found the Captain's phaser
on Deck 6,
but there's
no sign of her.
( dramatic theme playing )
Maintain a sensor lock
on that shuttle.
( equipment powering up )
I've got
main power back.
Engage warp engines.
Follow them.
WOMAN:
Aye, Commander.
( sighs )
They're approaching
warp 9.9.
Increase speed
to match.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Nearing
maximum warp velocity.
Structural collapse
is imminent.
( rumbling )
Are we in tractor range?
No. And they're still
accelerating. Warp 9.97.
COMPUTER:
Warning. At present speed,
structural failure
in 45 seconds.
Reduce speed
to warp 9.5.
Keep a sensor lock on them
as long as you can.
( console beeps )
I've lost them,
Commander.
They've gone
to transwarp.
( dramatic theme playing )
CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's log,
stardate 49373.4.
It's taken us three days
to locate the shuttle.
It appears to have dropped
out of transwarp
in an uninhabited
star system.
I've re-examined the data
on Mr. Paris' transformation
and I think I understand
what's happening to him.
The mutations
we observed are natural.
Natural.
The changes in his DNA
are consistent
with the evolutionary
development
of the
human genotype
observed over
the past 4 million years.
Increased brain capacity,
the loss of vestigial organs...
Are you saying
Lieutenant Paris
is evolving?
That's
my theory.
The only difference
between natural
evolution and what happened
to Mr. Paris
is that his changes took place
over a 24-hour period.
Somehow, traveling
at infinite velocity
accelerated the natural
human evolutionary process
by millions of years.
It's possible that
Mr. Paris represents
a future stage
in human development.
Although I can't say
it's very attractive.
What do we do about it?
I think my antiproton
approach was correct.
However, I'll need
to intensify the treatment
to restore
his original DNA.
( comlink beeps )
KIM: Bridge to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
KIM:
I think I found
the shuttlecraft, Commander.
It's on
the fourth planet
in one of the jungles
near the equator.
Acknowledged. Tuvok, have
a security team meet us
in Transporter
Room 3.
( crickets chirping )
( ominous theme playing )
( chittering )
( beeping )
There are traces
of human DNA.
It's them.
But I have
to admit...
I'm not sure which one
is the Captain.
The female...
obviously.
( chittering )
I don't know how I'm going
to enter this into the log.
I look forward to reading it.
CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's log,
supplemental.
We've transported the Captain
and Mr. Paris back to Sickbay.
As for their...offspring,
I've decided to leave them
in their new habitat.
I've eradicated
all traces
of the mutant DNA
from your system
and restored your
original genome.
Congratulations.
You're human again.
Thank you, doctor.
Captain, it'll take some time
for your genetic codes
to stabilize. I'd like you
to remain in Sickbay
for the next three days.
Just to be safe.
Excuse me.
PARIS:
Captain, uh...
I've thought
about having children.
But I must say, I never
considered having them with you.
( chuckles )
Captain, I'm sorry.
I-I don't know
what to say, except...
I don't remember
very much about...
Uh...
You know.
What makes you think
it was your idea?
Sometimes it's the female
of a species
that initiates mating.
But apology accepted,
nonetheless.
( chuckles )
You may be interested
to know I'm putting you in
for a commendation.
Regardless of the outcome,
you did make
the first transwarp flight.
Thank you, Captain.
Is there something wrong,
Lieutenant?
I don't know.
I guess this
whole experience
has left me feeling
a little overwhelmed.
Flying at warp 10...
Evolving into
a new lifeform,
mating, having
alien offspring...
You've broken more
than one record.
That's for sure.
( chuckles )
Breaking the threshold.
It was...
incredible.
But somehow, it doesn't mean
as much as I thought it would.
Oh?
I guess I went
into this
looking for a quick fix.
I thought making history
would change things,
not just
my service record...
My reputation.
If I'm not mistaken,
you've changed quite a few
minds on this ship.
You've earned a lot
of people's respect
and admiration.
Yeah.
But I'm starting
to realize
that it's not
other people's opinions
I should be worried about.
It's mine.
Heh, it seems,
Captain,
that I still have
a few barriers to break.
I just hope they're not
theoretical impossibilities.
Somehow...
I don't think they will be.
( dramatic theme playing )
( triumphant theme playing )