Game!
PARIS:
Why don't we
make it interesting
this time?
Let's add some table stakes.
What kind of stakes?
I don't know.
Mm, a couple of replicator
rations, maybe?
Don't do it, Harry.
He's hustling you.
Wait a minute.
Are you saying
he deliberately let me win?
( scoffs )
That would be dishonest,
Harry.
I won that game,
and I'll beat you again.
How many rations are you
willing to bet on that?
CREW: Come on, Harry.
A week's worth.
Harry, Harry, Harry.
Never, ever play
with anyone--
not even
your best friend--
if he says,
"Let's make it interesting."
Now, you want
a little action?
I'll give you
a little action.
How about an honest game
of chance?
Never play with anyone--
even your best friend--
if he offers you
"an honest game
of chance," Harry.
One replicator ration
is all it takes to play,
and the only thing
you have to do to win
is pick a number.
Just predict
what the radiogenic
particle count will be
at 1200 hours tomorrow,
and if you hit,
the pot is yours...
minus a small handling fee
for the bank, of course.
MAN 1:
I'll take a piece of that!
Jones, uh...
Harry, get a pad.
Take down these names
and numbers.
I'm in too.
MAN 2:
Lewis-- 2100.
MAN 3:
I'll back that bid up.
MAN 4:
Rogers...
Ensign Hogan, still no luck
with the warp drive?
No, Lieutenant.
The manifold just won't fire up.
We finally narrowed it down
to some kind of a problem
in EPS conduit 141.
Was there any indication
yesterday
that there was
something wrong?
Suder was monitoring
the EPS flow in the CCF.
He says everything
was fine.
Well, I guess we'll just
have to get in there
and track it down.
( indistinct chatter )
Happy Kal Rekk, Mr. Vulcan.
The holiday of Kal Rekk
is not for two weeks.
But it's the Kal Rekk season.
There is no Kal Rekk season.
Kal Rekk is a day of atonement,
solitude and silence.
Atonement. Solitude.
All your Vulcan holidays
are the same.
I've been doing
some research. I know.
Why would you need to do
research on Vulcan holidays?
It's part of my job
as Morale Officer.
Morale is irrelevant
to a Vulcan.
Oh, please.
There's no one on this ship
requires my services more
than you do.
I will not rest
until I see you smile.
Then you will not rest.
I don't suppose
you've ever heard
of the Vulcan Rumarie?
The Rumarie
is an ancient pagan festival.
Full of barely clothed
Vulcan men and women
covered
in slippery Rillan grease,
chasing one another.
That has not been observed
for a millennium.
Well, it's time
to bring it back.
TORRES:
Lieutenant Tuvok,
report to Engineering
immediately.
Acknowledged.
I've been thinking
of a Rumarie theme
for the mess hall
next week--
lots of high-fat, greasy foods,
and if people want
to take off their clothes
and chase one another,
well, it certainly wouldn't hurt
morale around here.
Is there a problem,
Lieutenant?
( suspenseful music playing )
( series theme playing )
98 percent of his body suffered
third-degree plasma burns.
If the circuit
hadn't failed,
he would have
been vaporized.
It appeared that Mr. Darwin
had entered the conduit
to repair a faulty circuit
when the accident occurred.
A perfectly good theory.
Unfortunately, it's wrong.
This contusion
is the result
of a hard blow
to the back of the skull.
Perhaps he fell
and hit his head in the conduit.
The coup-contrecoup
pattern of breakage
should tell us whether
the blow is a result
of a moving head hitting
a stationary object
or a moving object
hitting a stationary head.
In this case, the pattern
clearly indicates the latter.
I'm sorry to report
Crewman Darwin was murdered.
( dramatic music playing )
At first glance,
there is no obvious motive.
Crewman Darwin didn't have
any known enemies on board.
I've been looking over
his Starfleet record.
His training instructor
recommended him
as an officers candidate.
He turned it down
to come with us.
He has three sisters
back home.
( doors open )
Sorry I'm late.
These are the duty logs
from last night.
Lon Suder was the only one
in Engineering
when Frank Darwin
came on duty.
Something wrong?
No, not really.
I've just never been comfortable
with Suder, that's all.
It's not like he ever
did anything wrong.
It's just...
As a Maquis,
he did what he had to do
a little too well.
As in?
As in killing Cardassians.
I don't recall observing
anything unusual
about Mr. Suder's
behavior
while I was
on your ship.
You weren't with him
in battle.
Around us,
he was the quietest
most unassuming guy
you'll ever meet.
Typical Betazoid.
Kept to himself.
I never knew much
about him.
In the Maquis,
we didn't ask for résumés.
We needed all the help
we could get.
A lot of us were doing
what we were doing
to protect our families,
but Suder had
his own reasons.
I wish I could tell you
what they were.
In combat, there was
something in his eyes.
Maybe he had something personal
against Cardassians.
Sometimes I had to
pull him back,
stop him from going
too far,
and once or twice
when I did,
he looked at me
with those cold eyes,
and I just knew
he was this far away
from killing me.
I find it curious
that none of this was included
in your initial crew evaluation,
Commander.
I don't put down hunches
or bad feelings
in my crew evaluations,
Lieutenant.
A Vulcan
should appreciate that.
Considering the fact
that your Maquis crew
included malcontents,
outlaws and mercenaries,
I believe it would
have been appropriate.
I wasn't gonna make it harder
for any of them here.
Suder did his job
when he was serving with me,
and he's done his job
since he's been on this ship.
It seems clear
where your investigation
should begin, Lieutenant.
You wish to see me,
Mr. Tuvok?
Sit down.
You were alone
in Engineering
when Crewman Darwin reported
for duty last night.
Yes, sir.
Did you speak to him?
No, we just sort of looked
at each other,
and he did whatever he had to do
and I did what I had to do.
And what was that?
I was, um, running
a fuel-consumption analysis
for Lieutenant Torres.
She can tell you.
Are you accusing me
of killing him?
I have accused no one
at this time.
Did you kill Crewman Darwin?
No.
No. I barely knew him.
You know,
just because I'm a Maquis
doesn't make me a killer.
I will be speaking to everyone
in Engineering--
perhaps everyone on this ship--
not just former members
of the Maquis.
We all know how you feel
about the Maquis.
I assure you, I have no feelings
No, you just spied on us
and were gonna turn us all
over to Starfleet.
As hard as it may be
for you to understand,
that did not require
any feelings on my part.
The doctor places
the time of death at 2214.
Do you remember
what you were doing then?
I was still running
the fuel analysis.
I worked on it
until I went off duty.
Would you be surprised
to know
that your console
was logged off at 2209?
That's not possible.
Do you have a criminal record,
Mr. Suder?
Now, that would be
sort of difficult
to check on, wouldn't it?
Why would you have
any reason to lie?
I don't.
Do you have
a criminal record?
No.
How would you describe
your relationship
with Crewman Darwin?
I had no relationship.
No disagreements?
No.
No fights?
No reason to kill him?
No.
You are dismissed, crewman.
I may have more questions
for you later.
( suspenseful music playing )
( intercom beeps )
DOCTOR:
Medlab to Lieutenant Tuvok.
Go ahead, Doctor.
I think I've found something
that will help you.
Do you see the DNA strands
on the lower border?
TUVOK:
Yes.
They were retrieved
from inside the head wound
by nanites that I designed
to recognize
unusual DNA patterns.
This DNA was isolated
because it didn't belong
to the victim.
Have you matched it
to a member of the crew?
Are you certain?
DNA doesn't know how
to lie, Lieutenant.
( dramatic music playing )
I must advise you that
under Starfleet Directive 101,
you do not have to answer
any questions.
No.
No, there's no point
in denying it anymore.
Uh...
I used a 2-kilo coil spanner.
He was sitting at the...
impulse system control panel.
He didn't even look up
when I moved in behind him
and I swung the spanner
as hard as I could.
Crewman, I suggest you speak
to counsel.
There was practically no blood.
I was surprised at that.
I figured that the EPS conduit
was the easiest way
to dispose of the body,
but I must have damaged one
of the circuits
when I put him inside.
Oh...
I hid the spanner
behind a com line access panel
on Deck 7.
Why did you kill him,
Mr. Suder?
( sighs )
No reason.
That is not
a satisfactory answer.
You must have had some motive.
I didn't like the way
he looked at me.
( suspenseful music playing )
No doubt about it.
This is the murder weapon.
Mr. Suder is apparently
telling the truth.
You don't seem satisfied,
Lieutenant.
No.
You have a confession
and the murder weapon.
And no established motive.
Does it matter?
A crime must have
a logical purpose.
Ah, yes, I see--
how to close the case
without understanding the logic
of the crime.
For a Vulcan, that would be
a dilemma, wouldn't it?
Doctor, is it possible
that Mr. Suder is psychotic?
I doubt it.
Kes, call up
his genetic profile.
The neuro-genetic markers
are normal.
There's no tendency
toward bipolar disorder.
So he's not insane,
per se.
What do the elevated
norepinephrine levels suggest?
Aggressive,
even violent tendencies.
Why didn't you
report this immediately
after your examination,
Doctor?
These readings
are not significantly different
from those
of the other Maquis crewmen.
Obviously, it takes
a certain personality type
to be attracted
to the life of an outlaw.
Don't you believe
his confession, Tuvok?
In fact, I do.
Nevertheless, my job
is not finished
until I determine
a motive.
And what if
there was no motive?
One may not recognize
the motivation,
but there is always
motivation.
I think you are trapped
in your own Vulcan logic,
Lieutenant.
All of us
have violent instincts.
We have evolved from predators.
Well, not me, of course.
I've just been programmed
by you predators.
The question is,
in a civilized world,
can we suppress those instincts?
Most of the time, we can.
Vulcans certainly can.
You've got
your violent feelings buried
underneath centuries
of control,
but the rest
of the humanoid races
aren't always so skilled
at self-discipline.
Crewman Suder
may have violent impulses
that he just can't control.
Do you believe that a look
by Mr. Darwin
could provoke
such a violent reaction?
It has been known to happen.
I do not accept
that explanation.
( sighs )
I already told you
why I killed him, Lieutenant.
You didn't like
the way he looked at you.
Right.
Just how did he look at you?
Like a lot of people
in Starfleet do.
So this murder
could in fact be explained
as an outburst of rage
against Starfleet.
( snickers )
Look, if that's how you want
to look at this...
I want the truth.
I don't like Starfleet.
I won't deny that.
But...
Yes?
I have killed people
who weren't in Starfleet
for the same reason--
I did not like the way
they looked at me.
I've thought about
killing you, Lieutenant.
In my case,
you have a motive--
my previous mission as a spy,
my role as your accuser--
but to my knowledge,
Crewman Darwin
had done nothing to you.
That's true.
Then why choose him
as a victim?
I don't know.
Do you feel remorse?
( chuckles )
I don't seem
to feel anything at all.
Most Betazoids can sense
other people's emotions.
I can't even sense my own.
So what's gonna happen
to me now?
I'll have to discuss that
with the captain.
I know what I'd do
if I were her.
Guess I'm lucky.
The Federation
doesn't execute people.
( suspenseful music playing )
It is important
that I understand
why you killed Mr. Darwin.
I wish I could help you,
Lieutenant.
You can,
and indirectly,
I may be able to help you
as well.
Do you know
what a mind-meld is?
It's that... Vulcan thing
where you grab someone's head.
We would be
telepathically linked,
exchanging our thoughts,
in essence,
becoming one mind.
One mind? You and me?
I wouldn't recommend that,
Lieutenant.
It is not without risk,
but as a Vulcan,
I have internal processes
that allow me
to control violent instincts.
I believe I will be able
to suppress
whatever feelings I draw
from you.
And how will I be helped
by all this?
It is likely that you will gain,
at least for a time,
some of my self-discipline
to better control
your own violent nature.
What do I have to do?
Release the force field.
My mind to your mind...
your thoughts
to my thoughts.
( dramatic music playing )
COMPUTER:
Radiogenic particle density
at the measured coordinates
was 1873 per cubic meter.
( crew grumbling )
And the winner
of 16 replicator rations
in the Paris
radiogenic sweepstakes is...
Computer?
There is no winner today.
What? No winner?
Computer, are you positive?
Try your luck again.
Tomorrow you could be a winner.
Very funny.
You heard
the little lady.
Try your luck again,
folks.
The pot grows daily
until we have a winner.
Enter your name on the pad
and pick a number.
Can I buy you lunch,
Mr. Kim?
I have an extra ration
today.
Two, by my count.
Ten percent
of the day's action.
The only one who wins
every day is you.
I think I'll have
some prime rib--
medium rare--
mashed potatoes,
creamed spinach.
And maybe
some Yorkshire pudding...
and a Raktajino
with whipped cream on top.
So it ultimately
turned out
to be a worthwhile
and enlightening experience.
Did you get any of the answers
you were after?
It is difficult
for me to accept, Captain,
but Mr. Suder was telling
the truth as he knew it.
He is a man with
an incredibly violent nature
living in an environment
without any outlet
to express it.
I am surprised he was able
to maintain his self-control
for as long as he did.
I guess in his earlier life,
he always found ways
to release those impulses,
like volunteering
for the Maquis.
What do we do with him?
If we were home,
he'd be sent to prison.
The brig is the closest thing
we have,
but I don't think
we can just leave him
down in our dungeon
for the rest of the trip.
Nor would it be appropriate
to leave him in the custody
of someone in this quadrant.
I agree.
Captain...
he is prepared to die
for his crime.
An execution?
You're not seriously
suggesting that we--
I only mention it
because of the extenuating
circumstances
and because he feels
it would be
an appropriate punishment.
I don't.
I prefer to rehabilitate him,
not to end his life.
We'll confine him to quarters.
Work with Kim to install
maximum-security containment.
Pardon me, Captain,
but allowing him the comfort
of his own quarters
doesn't seem an appropriate
punishment for murder.
If we don't get home soon,
he'll be in that room
a long time, Mr. Tuvok.
I think this is the best
we can do
under these circumstances.
Crewman Darwin's three sisters
might not agree.
How is Suder
since the mind-meld?
Quite calm and controlled.
Clearly, the meld initiated
some high cortical activity
in his brain.
And you, Tuvok--
any adverse effects?
I will admit
that I am more disconcerted
than I anticipated.
Why don't you take a day or two
off for meditation?
Thank you,
but I am already taking steps
to purge
these residual feelings.
I don't believe time off
will be necessary.
I will, of course, advise you
of any further complications.
Tuvok.
Take care of yourself.
( dramatic music playing )
I would prefer
to be alone.
Okay. All right.
Far be it from me
to bother anyone.
If you really
want me to leave,
I'll leave.
I really want you to leave.
I don't believe you.
Your voice says, "go away,"
but your heart wants me
to make you smile.
Please, go away.
Come on. A little smile.
How is it gonna hurt?
I won't tell anyone.
What must I do
to convince you to stop?
Come on. Just a little,
itty-bitty smile.
Just let the mouth curl
a little there.
Ha-ha. That's g--
You know,
there's an old Talaxian song
my mother used to sing me
as a child.
I'm gonna sing it to you
every day from now on. It goes--
( choking )
Mr. Vulcan, I--
Oh, I can't breathe.
Can't-- I can't breathe.
Please, I'm sorry if I-I--
Computer,
end holodeck program.
COMPUTER:
Particle density
at the measured coordinates
was 1415 per cubic meter.
And the winner is?
Computer?
CHAKOTAY:
There won't be
any more winners.
( crew grumbling )
Oh, come on, Chakotay.
We were just having
a little fun,
the recreational facilities
of the Delta Quadrant
being what they are.
I've heard you're responsible
for this, Lieutenant.
I didn't think Starfleet
would have a problem with it.
With a senior officer
running a gambling operation
and skimming profits
from each day's proceeds?
Now, why would Starfleet
have a problem with that?
Since you all seem to have
extra replicator rations,
you won't be needing these.
Today's pot
is hereby confiscated.
CREWMAN 1: Oh, come on.
CREWMAN 2: Jeez, wait a minute.
The captain's put a lot of faith
in you, Mr. Paris.
She'll be disappointed.
You're on report.
Now, there's a tough job--
filling out reports.
But somebody's gotta do it.
Thanks a lot.
I did not hear you come in,
Lieutenant.
How are you feeling?
Centered.
Don't be misled.
Your violent instincts
still exist.
You are simply suppressing them,
as Vulcans do.
I can feel the difference.
It is almost as if I can observe
the violence inside me
without letting it
get too close.
It is quite remarkable
what you Vulcans
have learned to do.
Understand that this will not
be a permanent change
unless you commit
to a strict daily regime
of meditation
and mental exercise.
I also believe that a series
of holodeck programs
designed to allow
your violent tendencies
to be released
in a safe environment
may help to purge
your aggressive impulses.
Holographic violence
does not give
the same... sensation
as the real thing.
I've tried it.
Has anyone ever suggested
targeted neuro-synaptic therapy?
That didn't work either.
Our doctor is programmed
with the medical knowledge
of every Federation world.
Perhaps he'll know of some
treatment you haven't tried.
Since the meld, I feel capable
of controlling myself.
Perhaps with your help,
I can learn to stay this way.
It must be difficult for you.
Difficult?
Knowing violence
as I've known it.
I have studied violence
for over 100 years.
Studying it
and knowing it
are two different things,
aren't they?
It's attractive, isn't it?
Attractive?
Violence.
On the contrary.
I find it disturbing.
You're right.
It is disturbing--
never knowing
when that impulse may come
or whether or not
you can control it when it does.
You live on the edge
of every moment,
and yet, in its own way,
violence is attractive too.
Maybe because
it doesn't require logic.
Perhaps that's why
it's so liberating.
Ironic, isn't it--
that I can share with you,
of all people,
what I have hidden from everyone
all my life.
Can we do it again, Tuvok?
Again?
Meld.
That would not be advisable.
I understand.
Really, I do.
I have thought about it a lot.
In a way, a mind-meld is almost
an act of violence, isn't it?
I don't understand
why you would--
Penetration.
Your will dissolving mine.
The joining.
It seems to me
that a mind-meld
might be fatal
if you lost control.
Computer, place level one
security seals on this room.
Acknowledged.
Security seals in place.
Delete security clearance
Tuvok 1-4-9-4 lambda.
Specified
security clearance deleted.
Please inform the captain
that I am no longer fit
for duty.
Acknowledged.
Computer, lift
the security seal
from Lieutenant Tuvok's
quarters.
( electronic beep )
Wait here.
( labored breathing )
I would advise you
not to enter, Captain.
Tuvok.
Please, do not come any closer.
Talk to me.
I said...
don't come any closer.
We need to get you to Sick Bay.
It would be safer for the crew
if I were to remain
in these quarters.
I remind you, I am trained
in the martial arts
of many Alpha Quadrant
cultures.
Sitting here,
attempting to meditate,
I have counted
the number of ways
I know of killing someone
using just a finger,
a hand... a foot...
I had reached 94
when you entered.
The doctor is fully versed
in Vulcan medicine.
( labored breathing )
Again, for safety reasons,
I recommend you sedate me
before you initiate transport.
KES:
Levels of neuropeptides
in the limbic system
are down 15 percent.
There's a definite
neurochemical imbalance
in the mesiofrontal
cortex.
Which means what?
That's where the Vulcan
psycho-suppression systems
are located.
This may be the result
of a incompatibility
with the Betazoid
telepathic neural center.
I'm not sure.
( sighs )
Vulcan mind-melds.
Utter foolishness.
Anybody with an ounce
of sense
wouldn't share his brain
with someone else.
Would you?
I certainly wouldn't.
And of course,
when something goes wrong--
And believe me, it does,
more often than they'd like
to admit--
the first thing they call out
is, "Doctor."
Can you help him?
I wish I could tell you.
There's a recommended course
of treatments
that should begin immediately.
What does it involve?
First we have to take away his
ability to control his violence.
We do this in short bursts
over a period of time
and hope it provides a shock
to his system.
If it works,
his own neural controls
will take over again.
I believe we're about ready.
Revive him.
( electronic beep )
Something has changed.
We've temporarily removed all
of your emotional suppression
abilities, Lieutenant.
How do you feel?
( gasping )
I... feel.
Tuvok, do you know
where you are?
( laughs )
Of course I know where I am,
Captain.
I'm just not sure I know
who I am.
Try to relax.
The treatment still has
about three minutes to go.
Oh, it must be working,
because I feel very strong.
Very... powerful.
Quite euphoric.
This must be how
my ancestors felt.
Doctor, would you
consider allowing me
to remain this way
for a while?
It would be
a valuable opportunity
for me to study
primal Vulcan behavior.
Sorry, I'm not prepared
to do that.
The course of treatment
is very specific.
You are not invulnerable,
hologram.
A few well-chosen commands
to the computer,
and you will cease to exist.
( grunts )
( electronic beep )
Two minutes,
30 seconds left.
You look shocked, Captain.
You must be asking yourself,
what if this doesn't wok?
What do we do then?
I have an idea.
I'll just stay in my quarters
for the rest of the trip.
I'll just relax
and read,
eat the ship's food,
use the ship's energy,
all in the comforts
of my own room.
Why, even Mr. Suder and I
could get together
for a few hands
of Cardassian Pinochle
once or twice a week.
That is how we treat
violent offenders
on this ship, isn't it?
You are not
a violent offender, Tuvok.
I could be.
Just like Suder.
You know, Captain, I don't mind
telling you something
the other Tuvok never would.
You are wrong.
Sparing Suder's life
is a sign of weakness.
You disgust me.
All you humans do.
Admit it.
Part of you feels as I do.
Part of you wants him to die
for what he did.
No part of me feels that way.
Liar!
He has killed,
and you know he deserves to die!
On behalf
of the victim's family, Captain,
I beg you to reconsider.
Give them the satisfaction
of his execution.
I have a radical suggestion,
Captain.
Release the force field,
and I'll kill him for you.
Release the force field.
My student--
my protégé.
There is so much to learn
for each of us today,
isn't there?
You'll be all right, Tuvok.
This will be over
in 30 seconds.
Listen to what I tell you.
Release the force field.
I'm sorry. I had them disable
your telepathic abilities too.
You can't reach me, Tuvok.
Release the force field!
( grunting )
Ten seconds.
Five seconds.
( gasps )
It's over.
He's lost consciousness.
He might be able
to fool the sensors.
Sedate him again.
Computer, remove
the force field.
( electronic buzz )
Help me get him
back on the bed.
How many treatments
do you think will be necessary?
I wish I knew, Captain.
In a sense, Mr. Tuvok's mind
is fighting a classic battle
between good and evil.
The battle may be won
in a day, a year,
or it may never be won.
( suspenseful music playing )
( groaning )
( grunts )
( gasping )
( man groans )
( thump )
Tuvok?
I wondered
what happened to you.
They wouldn't tell me
anything.
There were some complications
from the meld.
I wondered about that.
I've been undergoing
neuro-synaptic therapy
in Sick Bay.
It didn't work.
No.
Have you come to kill me?
To execute you for your crime.
To execute me. I see.
And calling it that makes it
more comfortable for you.
I will take no comfort in this.
A most logical use
of violence--
to punish the violent.
We both know
that I am prepared to die,
but are you prepared
to kill?
It needs to be done.
To release
your violent impulses?
To serve justice.
Justice or vengeance?
Understand one thing,
Tuvok.
I can promise you
this will not silence
your demons.
If you can't control
the violence,
the violence controls you.
Be prepared to yield
your entire being to it,
to sacrifice your place
in civilized life,
for you will no longer
be a part of it,
and there's no return.
( grunts )
I...
seek...
no return.
Of course. You would not
be able to live with yourself.
Then we are both to die,
and that will end
the torment.
My mind to your mind.
My thoughts
to your thoughts.
My mind... to your mind.
My thoughts
to your thoughts.
( both gasping )
( groans )
Crewman Suder to the bridge.
CHAKOTAY:
Suder, what are you doing
with a com-badge?
You better get down here,
Chakotay.
Lieutenant Tuvok needs help.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
Ensign Suder
has been incarcerated
in secured quarters,
where he will likely spend
the rest of our journey home.
Lieutenant Tuvok remains
under observation
in Sick Bay.
It may be hard for you
to believe, Lieutenant,
but what happened
is encouraging.
Your inability
to complete the act of murder
shows your suppression systems
are starting to function again.
You're on your way back
to being normal.
Although I'm not sure
how the word "normal" applies
to a species that suppresses
all their emotions.
( hoarsely ):
Captain...
I must apologize
for my inappropriate behavior.
I'm just glad
we have you back, Mr. Tuvok.
I was most... insulting to you.
Don't worry about it.
I've been insulted before.
I hope you understand
that I have always had
the greatest respect
for you as a captain
and consider you... a friend.
That means a great deal to me.
Enough said.
Get some rest.
Tuvok.
No more mind-melds
without my permission.
Understood?
( dramatic music playing )
( series theme playing )