I've been considering
naming him after my husband.
It's been a tradition
in his family
for over five
generations.
I'm sure
he'd be very pleased.
My husband's name is..
Greskrendtregk.
He's Ktarean.
Choosing a name
is no easy matter.
I speak
from experience.
Have you had
any progress, Doctor?
( sighs )
I've reviewed
historical, literary
and anthropological databases
from over 500 worlds,
and have yet to find
a suitable name.
However, I may want
to give some thought to...
Greskrendtregk.
To be honest,
I've been thinking
of something simpler.
What do you think
of Cameron?
Oh, I like it.
Cameron. From
the ancient
Celtic term for one
whose nose is bent.
Well, what about Frederick?
Frederick.
Very distinguished.
However, it bears
a close resemblance
to a rather impolite term
on the Bolian home world.
Well, it doesn't have
to be a human name.
I like Sural.
It's Vulcan.
Yes. Unfortunately,
it was also the name
of a dictator on Sakura Prime,
famed for beheading his rivals
and his parents.
He won't have
an objection to Benaren.
You're right. I've never heard
that name before.
I think it's lovely.
Is it Ocampan?
Benaren was
my father's name.
He was the greatest
inspiration in my life.
JANEWAY: All science officers
please report to your stations.
Your scans look fine, Ensign.
We'll see you in a week.
Thank you.
Greskrendtregk
would make
a good middle name,
don't you think?
You never suggested
your father's name to me.
I-I thought you were only
considering human names.
Ah. Well, you
were mistaken.
If you like Benaren,
there's no reason
you can't use it too.
I'm sure she won't mind.
Won't mind that I just
usurped her baby's name
the moment I heard it?
Thank you, but
no, thank you.
My uncle's name
was Elrem.
I once knew
a boy named Tarrik.
PARIS:
There's not much left
of whatever it was.
From the amount of debris,
I'd guess it was a small ship,
no bigger than a shuttlecraft.
I'm not reading
any organic material
in the debris field.
It must have
been an unmanned vessel.
Possibly a probe.
Any idea
what happened to it?
The high residual
energy signature
indicates
repeated weapons fire.
Captain, the wreckage
is composed primarily
of duritanium polyalloy.
Duritanium?
I haven't seen many weapons
that could do
that kind of damage
to a duritanium hull.
Transport some samples
of the debris
to Engineering
for analysis.
Continuous scans,
Lieutenant.
We don't want
whoever did this
to catch us
by surprise.
Any conclusions?
Afraid so.
We've identified
the signature
left by the weapons fire.
There's no question.
It was Cardassian.
Cardassian?
Could Seska be responsible?
No, Captain.
I am.
( dramatic
theme music playing )
The probe was destroyed
by an experimental
Cardassian weapon
from the Alpha Quadrant.
( panting )
Sorry.
I recognized
its signature because...
because I know
this weapon very well.
Chakotay and I
got our hands on it
when we were fighting
the Cardassians.
How did it get here?
Probably the
same way we did.
The last time we saw it, it was
heading in the same direction
in the badlands where
the caretaker picked us up.
Originally, the Cardassians
sent this thing to destroy
a Maquis
munitions base.
We nicknamed it,
"Dreadnought."
It's a self-guided
tactical missile
carrying a charge
of 1,000 kilos of matter
and another 1,000
of antimatter.
Enough to destroy
a small moon.
Now, add to that,
one of the most sophisticated
computer systems I've ever seen.
They made this missile
adaptable, evasive,
armed with its own
defensive weaponry--
in other words, unstoppable.
So, how did you stop it?
We didn't.
It got through all our defenses.
Worked like it was supposed to,
except for one minor detail.
It didn't go off.
Leave it to the Cardassians
to build such an incredibly
advanced tactical weapon
and then arm the warhead
with an old kinetic detonator.
CHAKOTAY:
The missile skipped off
into the atmosphere and
quietly went into orbit.
I got inside it,
and reprogrammed the computer.
( sighs )
Hell, I didn't
just reprogram it.
I changed its identity.
I made it forget
about being Cardassian.
Now it was working
for the Maquis.
And we gave it
a new mission--
to destroy the Cardassian
fuel depot on Aschelan Five.
But it never made it
out of the badlands.
We thought it had
been destroyed in one
of the plasma storms.
So, how do we
stop this weapon
before it causes
any more damage?
Dreadnought
masks its warp trail
with a randomized EM field,
but I can modify
our navigational sensors
to cut through that.
And what are we going to do
with it once we find it?
I get back inside it.
I know all the security codes.
I installed them myself.
Lieutenant Paris
can assist you
with the navigational
sensors.
Keep me informed.
Dismissed.
Lieutenant? I expect everyone
to show up for meetings on time
and properly dressed.
Yes, sir.
There's still
a lot of distortion
in the upper frequencies.
Better. Now let's
try filtering out
the ion radiation.
B'Elanna.
You must be really worried
about catching this thing.
Chakotay wasn't telling
the whole truth.
We didn't send Dreadnought
on a mission
against the Cardassians.
I was the one who sent it...
without asking him.
You were afraid
he'd say no.
After I did it,
he pulled me aside, and...
I was ready to defend myself.
I was so sure
that I had anticipated
everything that could
possibly go wrong.
I even programmed it
to warn Federation ships
to stay out of its way.
In my own voice.
Your voice?
Listening to that
Cardassian computer's voice
was driving me crazy.
Heh. I don't blame you.
Anyway, Chakotay
looked at me--
I didn't know him
very well yet--
and all he said
in that damned
soft voice of his was...
that I'd hurt him.
That he thought he'd earned
my trust and loyalty.
I was so glad
when it disappeared
into the badlands.
I remember thinking,
"Thank God it's over."
But it's not.
And if anything happens here
because of Dreadnought...
it's my fault.
No one else's.
( sighs )
You took a risk.
You were thinking
like a Maquis.
That was a whole
different life.
( gasps )
Tell me about it.
You know...
I've been surprised
at how well you've been
able to fit in here.
A little envious too.
Tom...
what's been going on
with you lately?
Going on? How?
( scoffs )
People are starting
to talk.
Are they?
People like who? Chakotay?
No, I mean people
like me.
Like today.
Look at yourself.
Coming to
a briefing late?
And is it true
that you had a fight
with Lieutenant Rollins?
( chuckling )
The lieutenant
was unhappy
that my conn reports
weren't punctuated properly,
according
to Starfleet protocol.
I didn't like his attitude.
Was he right
about your reports?
We're in the Delta Quadrant;
nowhere near Starfleet.
What difference...?
Yeah. He was right.
I'm the one who's been wrong.
Wrong about a lot of things.
Why don't we try running
a multi-phasic sweep?
( gentle
dramatic theme playing )
Captain, I'm picking up
the trail again.
New heading: 1-9-6 mark 4.
I'm on it.
This course is erratic.
Are we sure we're following
a single warp trail?
Perhaps its navigational system
is malfunctioning.
It's been operating
for over a year, far longer
than it was designed
to function.
No. This is deliberate.
It's following
one of the evasive patterns
I programmed into it.
It must have
observed us following.
I think I've got it
on long-range sensors.
No, that's a sensor echo.
Dreadnought's programmed
to deflect its image
up to 100,000 kilometers
from its true location.
The next time
you get a heading,
look for a brief surge
in neutrino emissions
within 100,000-kilometer radius.
That'll be the real thing.
Got it.
Elevated neutrino levels.
Locking in coordinates.
It's within
visual range.
On screen.
Its targeting scanners
have been activated.
What's wrong?
It's not supposed
to do that
until it's locked
onto its final target.
It's heading for a planet
in a system
over ten light years away.
At its current speed,
it'll get there
in about three weeks.
The planet is Class M.
I'm reading several
heavily-populated areas.
( dramatic theme playing )
Seska will want to know
about this Cardassian missile
immediately.
Mr. Jonas, your enthusiasm
is appreciated,
but I would prefer
to know more about it
before I bring it
to Maje Culluh's attention.
If I could just talk to Seska.
As I explained,
I have now been
assigned to be your control.
Look, has she been made aware of
how much I've been helping you?
What the Maje chooses to share
with her is none of my concern.
But you are in good hands,
my friend.
Now, tell me more about this
weapon your ship has found.
Look, all you need
to tell Seska
is that missile is better armed
than entire Kazon-Nistrim sect.
( alarm beeping )
That's very
interesting.
What more can you tell me
that I can...?
Someone's about to make
a subspace transmission.
They may be able to detect
our comlink.
I have to terminate.
My name is Kathryn Janeway,
Captain of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
First Minister
Kellan, Captain.
What is it you want?
Our scans of your world
suggest you have
long-range tracking abilities.
We have been observing your
course for the last two days.
Have you also been able
to detect the missile
on a parallel course
off our starboard bow?
We haven't been able
to identify
what it is, but yes.
You have the right to know,
First Minister,
that this missile
is carrying a warhead
with a significant
destructive force, and--
Is this some sort
of threat, Captain?
On the contrary.
We want to help.
I find that hard to believe.
Your reputation
precedes you, Captain.
We've been told that
you've threatened many races
since your arrival
in this quadrant.
First Minister,
we're aware
the Kazon have been
telling that to people.
They'd like to prevent us
from making allies.
I assure you,
you've been misled.
And yet here you are,
sending this missile toward us.
The missile arrived here
from our quadrant
due to
a very unusual accident.
We haven't been able
to determine yet
why it chose Rakosa
as its target,
but my chief engineer
is preparing
to disarm it
before it reaches you.
Perhaps
you are telling me this
in order to delay
our defensive response.
I could have maintained
communication silence
and not given you
any warning at all.
That's true.
Nevertheless,
be aware that
I am placing
our defense force on alert.
I'd do the same in your place.
We will be watching
your progress closely.
Janeway to Torres.
How soon
will you be ready to transport?
Dreadnought's shields
have responded to my codes.
I'm ready now, Captain.
JANEWAY: Proceed.
Energize.
DREADNOUGHT COMPUTER
( with Torres' voice ):
Authorized entry detected.
Initiating DNA scan.
B'Elanna Torres confirmed.
Hello, B'Elanna.
Your last systems access
was on Stardate 47582.
Current date is 49447.
Time: 0840 hours.
Did you sleep well
last night?
Not so well,
to tell you the truth.
Activate programmer interface.
Your presence
was not anticipated
during the mission.
Please explain.
Something's gone wrong with
your programming, Dreadnought.
Display targeting schematic.
A self-diagnostic
has been conducted
every 14 hours.
No malfunctions
have been detected.
Maybe there's something wrong
with
your diagnostic systems too.
( sighs )
Identify target.
Aschelan Five.
What targeting parameters
are you using?
Size, radiothermic signature,
atmospheric composition,
relative...
Enough.
Dreadnought,
you're nowhere near
Aschelan Five.
Based on available data,
you are mistaken, B'Elanna.
Let me check out
your navigational systems.
Access to primary
navigational systems
is denied
at Stage Three Alert status.
That was my idea,
wasn't it?
Affirmative.
Okay.
We'll have to go at this
in a different way then,
won't we?
( device beeps on;
beeping )
Dreadnought,
do you know what happened to you
the day after
my last systems access?
Please be more specific.
Did you encounter
a coherent Tetryon beam?
Confirmed.
All attempts
to avoid the phenomenon failed.
That beam carried you
into the Delta Quadrant.
I'm not surprised
it damaged your sensors.
( device turns off )
Dreadnought, reinitialize
your navigational systems.
Computer?
Reinitialization sequence
is complete.
Okay...
Now verify
our current position.
Based on relative position
to known astronomical markers,
this vessel
is currently located
in the Delta Quadrant.
And is Aschelan Five
located in the Delta Quadrant?
Negative.
Then reconfirm your target lock.
Unable to verify.
Standing down
from Stage Three.
Target lock
has been deactivated.
Reestablishing Stage Four.
Janeway to Torres.
Go ahead, Captain.
We're showing a shut-down
of all your engines.
Can you confirm that?
That and more.
I'll be ready to transport back
in a few minutes.
Acknowledged.
Good work, B'Elanna.
Janeway out.
Dreadnought,
return to Stage Five.
Initiate powersave program.
Acknowledged.
Good night, B'Elanna.
( systems powering down )
Sweet dreams.
The Dreadnought's quantum
torpedoes could be modified
to be compatible
with our launchers.
What about its
engine components?
Easily converted
to Starfleet specs.
We'll have
spare parts for years.
We should also
download some files
from the computer core.
B'Elanna,
you can begin
the salvage operation
first thing in the--
Paris to Janeway.
Yes, Lieutenant?
The missile just took off.
It's going into warp.
Stay with it, Tom.
Engaging warp drive.
This is impossible.
When I left,
it was
completely shut down.
We're back on a heading
to Rakosa Five.
It's increasing
speed to warp nine.
At this rate, it'll reach
the planet in 51 hours.
( dramatic score playing )
PARIS: It's still on course
for the planet at warp nine.
JANEWAY: Mr. Paris, bring us
within ten kilometers.
Maintain
a parallel position.
Bridge to Torres.
Your status?
I don't understand it, Captain.
Dreadnought's shields
are not recognizing
my security code anymore.
We can't
initiate transport.
You better get back up here,
Lieutenant.
( sighs )
Aye, Captain.
Mr. Tuvok, let's take a shot
at disabling its drive systems.
Ready photons. Red Alert.
Torres programmed
the missile's shields
to adjust to all known
weapons, even Starfleet's.
Voyager wasn't in service
when she did it.
We're equipped
with Type-Six photon torpedoes.
They may just get through.
Fire.
No discernible
damage, Captain.
It must have
scanned our weapons,
adapted its shields.
Captain, it's maintaining
course and speed.
We're being hailed
by the missile.
Let's hear it.
DREADNOUGHT ( Torres' voice ):
Unidentified Federation ship,
although this vessel
is Cardassian in design,
it has been appropriated
by the Maquis.
Please stand down
your weapons.
You stand down your weapons
and I'll stand down mine.
You are interfering
with a tactical mission
against Cardassian aggressors.
This vessel is programmed
to respond
with all necessary force
to prevent any disruption
to its mission.
Dreadnought,
why have you resumed course?
Hello, B'Elanna.
Course was resumed
once your safe departure
from this vessel
was confirmed.
It was a necessary response
to your deception.
My "deception"?
You are participating in
the Delta Quadrant deception.
Explain, Dreadnought.
False information
has been entered
into Dreadnought's
navigational sensor array.
When a bomb starts talking
about itself
in the third person,
I get worried.
Why would I enter
false information?
Probability assessment
indicates
you are being coerced
by Cardassian forces.
You've already
identified Voyager
as a Federation ship,
Dreadnought.
Your scanners
must indicate
this is not
a Cardassian crew.
Probability assessment
indicates
you are operating
within the parameters
of the Cardassian-Federation
alliance,
as described
in the Treaty of 2367,
a treaty rejected
by the Maquis.
So when
I was just over there,
and you shut yourself off,
you were lying to me?
Acknowledged.
Heh. I never taught it
to do that.
That is not correct, B'Elanna.
Your tactical subroutine
instructed Dreadnought
to prepare responses
for 39 potential
Cardassian threats.
The possibility of your capture
and coercion was number seven.
Dreadnought, is there any way
we can prove to you
that you are actually
in the Delta Quadrant,
that this is
not a deception?
The probability of being
in the Delta Quadrant,
75,000 light years
from last confirmed location,
is negligible.
The target is located
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Target lock
has been established.
There will be
no further warnings.
Terminating
communications link.
( comm link beeps off )
The one possible
vulnerability I remember
is in the thoron
shock emitter.
If we can get it
to fire at full power,
that should destabilize
the reactor core for 30 seconds.
A single sustained
tachyon beam
might just penetrate that core
and destroy it.
What will it take to provoke
Dreadnought into firing?
It shouldn't be that difficult.
Once we go after it
with an all-out assault,
the emitter should fire.
Mr. Tuvok,
set your target.
JANEWAY:
Ready photons.
Ready, Captain.
Fire.
The missile's
thoron shock emitter has fired.
( rumbling )
Initiate the tachyon beam.
We have penetrated its shields.
Direct hit
to the core.
KIM: Reading an energy
build-up in its reactor.
It should overload
in about 30 seconds.
Wait a minute.
There's a plasma surge
coming from its core.
What the hell?
( electric zapping )
( rumbling )
Report!
It sent a plasma burst
along the tachyon beam
into our main power system.
We've got E.P.S. relays
burnt out all over the ship.
I'm not getting response
from warp or impulse drives.
Even maneuvering
thrusters are out.
TUVOK: The missile was
not significantly damaged.
It has maintained
its course for Rakosa.
( dramatic theme playing )
Our engines will be back on line
in less than an hour,
First Minister.
Then we'll try again.
Did you sustain
any casualties, Captain?
A few. A broken arm,
a broken leg.
Fortunately, that's all.
I'm pleased to hear that.
We are projecting casualties
at two million
if the worst occurs.
I have deployed our fleet
to intercept this missile
in a matter of hours.
First Minister, we've analyzed
your offensive capabilities,
and they're no match
for what you're facing.
You must have
realized that yourself.
And what
would you have me do?
Sit here and wait for death
to fall from the sky?
( sighs )
I'm sorry.
We haven't had much sleep.
We weren't prepared
for anything like this.
We are not a warlike race.
We haven't devoted
our resources
to building weapons
like yours.
First Minister...
Please.
I've always
hated that title.
My name is Kellan.
I prefer that.
Our chief engineer
is trying to return
to the missile's
control room.
She's still our best chance
at disarming it.
There's no reason to send your
fleet on a hopeless mission.
I appreciate
your efforts, truly,
but the decision
has been made.
We have
some good pilots, Captain.
Perhaps
they will surprise you.
( gentle
dramatic theme playing )
( beeping and buzzing )
KIM: Blocked again.
( sighs )
We don't have time for this.
Don't worry, we'll find a way
to get you back over there.
We wouldn't have to if
I'd done my job right
the first time.
You couldn't expect to guess
every move it made.
Why not? Dreadnought seems
pretty good at guessing mine.
It's only as smart
as you made it.
I'm not so sure
about that, Harry.
Its programs are adaptive,
and it's been accumulating data
all this time.
It spends every minute
of every day
thinking
about new strategies,
new probabilities.
And I bet it doesn't
spend much time
worrying about what it
could have done differently.
All right, Starfleet,
let's give it another try.
DREADNOUGHT:
Unauthorized entry detected.
Initiating DNA scan.
Hello, B'Elanna.
Your last systems access
was today at 0840 hours.
Current time is 1931 hours.
Have you had a pleasant day?
Oh, yeah. Swell day.
Access to programmer
interface has been denied.
( electrical crackle )
Access to circuit pathways
has been denied.
Be advised that the intensity
of the shock will increase
if you attempt to open
the panel again.
( scanning device beeping )
( high-pitched beeping )
( scanning device beeps )
( electrical whirring )
I'm disappointed in you,
Dreadnought.
If I really was
a Cardassian agent,
you should have killed me
with the first charge.
Probability assessment
indicates
that you are being coerced
by Cardassian forces.
Somehow I expected you
to put up more of a fight.
( systems powering down )
Computer?
Stage Two Alert
has been activated.
Tell me what's happening.
There are 15 priority targets
approaching.
All weapons systems
at full readiness.
Speed: Full impulse.
The Rakosan fleet.
( dramatic theme playing )
Hail the lead ship.
Channel open, Captain.
Audio only.
This is Captain Janeway
on Voyager.
I urge you
to break off your attack.
One of my crew members
is aboard the missile.
MALE PILOT: You'd better get
your crewman out, Captain.
We estimate time
to intercept: 90 seconds.
We're still attempting
to disarm its weapons.
My orders are clear.
You'll have to talk
to my superiors back home.
Rakosa One, out.
Janeway to Torres.
TORRES: Yes, Captain.
The Rakosan fleet
is preparing to attack.
Captain, don't beam me out.
I may not be able
to transport back here again.
Lieutenant...
I'm making progress.
The Rakosan ships
have created a diversion.
I've already used it to disarm
the security codes on board.
If I can just get
to the central processor,
I can disable the entire system.
Alright. We'll try to keep
a transporter lock on you.
Janeway out.
( monitor beeping )
The Rakosan attack
is commencing, Captain.
Move us into weapons
range, Mr. Paris.
Aye, Captain.
Give them some cover fire.
Red Alert.
Firing phasers.
( rumbling from phaser strikes )
DREADNOUGHT: All command control
functions have been rerouted
through protected
backup circuits, B'Elanna.
Your attempt to compromise
weapons control
has been blocked.
Those ships aren't your enemy.
They are not Cardassian.
Can't you recognize that?
This vessel is programmed
to respond
with all necessary force
to prevent any disruption
to its mission.
Shields are holding.
We are drawing minimal fire
from the missile.
Its primary weapon systems
are focused on the
Rakosan vessel.
Another group of fighters
is starting an attack run.
We've got to draw more
of the missile's fire.
Make Voyager
a more serious threat, Tuvok.
Shields at 40%.
Damage reported on
decks three and four.
Repair crews
responding.
The Rakosan vessels
are withdrawing, Captain.
Good. Move us out
of range of the plasma wave.
Janeway to Torres.
Yes, Captain.
The Rakosan ships
have retreated.
We have one hour
and nine minutes
until the missile reaches
the planet. Any progress?
Dreadnought's created
backup systems
to replace the ones
I tried to disable.
Do you have any other ideas?
I'm reluctant to discuss them
in present company.
But could you
send over a...?
( static )
Captain?
DREADNOUGHT: Communications
have been terminated.
Transporter lock
has also been disengaged.
( chuckling )
What took you so long?
There was a tactical advantage
in monitoring
your ship's communications
until this time.
So...
It's just you and me now...
You are accessing
the detonation control circuit.
Probability assessment
indicates
you are attempting
to detonate the explosive
before it reaches its target.
( scoffs )
Now, that wouldn't make
much sense, would it?
I'd be killing myself
in the process.
Probability assessment
indicates
you are attempting to detonate
the explosive
before it reaches its target.
If I'm being coerced
by Cardassians,
why would I be willing
to sacrifice myself for them?
Answer that one.
Unable to respond.
Reassessing probabilities.
Ah-ha.
Gotcha.
Why don't we reassess
those probabilities together?
Okay?
Remember how we used to play
hypothetical games?
Affirmative.
Let's play one now.
Here's a hypothetical
situation for you.
Suppose I've been telling you
the truth all along,
and you really are
in the Delta Quadrant...
Probability of being
in the Delta Quadrant,
75,000 light years
from last confirmed location,
is negligible.
"Hypothetical,"
Dreadnought.
It's a game, remember?
Assume it's true for a moment.
Assumption entered.
And we're heading
for the wrong target...
Assumption entered.
Millions of innocent people
are about to die
when you detonate.
Assumption entered.
Now explain to me
how this might happen.
If key sensor programs
were damaged or deleted,
data banks
would be compromised.
Just for the fun of it...
Let's have a look
at those data banks,
see if anything looks
at all... "compromised."
Is this
a complete file directory?
There seem
to be a few missing.
Files containing information
about the weapons
or tactical systems
are not necessary
to verify sensor accuracy.
Oh, I'm hurt.
You don't trust me.
Hold on.
Pause the display.
What's that?
Computer, identify
the Cardassian file on screen.
Unable to identify.
It looks like a backup file.
Computer,
when was this file created?
Stardate 46437.5.
I believe that
was before you and I ever met.
Hypothetical game
terminated.
Probability reassessment
complete.
A new conclusion?
Affirmative.
Probability of being
in the Delta Quadrant
remains negligible.
When that option is rejected,
new probability assessment
indicates
that you have changed
loyalties, B'Elanna.
You are now cooperating
No...
with the Cardassian
Federation alliance
as described
in the Treaty of 2367,
a treaty which has been
rejected by the Maquis.
Dreadnought...
Humanoid life support
aboard this vessel
has been terminated.
( systems powering down )
Approaching target
at full impulse.
( alarm blaring )
Stage One Alert
has been activated.
Initiating
final detonation sequence.
People are crowding
every port
trying to get off
the eastern continent.
There aren't enough ships.
Kellan,
there are still 41 minutes
for us to prevent this.
What can be done
in 41 minutes?
I'm prepared to use this ship
to detonate the warhead
before the missile
reaches you.
Use your ship?
To collide with it?
Something like that.
Do you really think
that would work?
I'm not sure.
You would sacrifice yourselves
to benefit a people you didn't
even know two days ago?
To save two million lives?
That's not a hard decision.
Your reputation
in this quadrant
isn't deserved, Captain.
For what it's worth...
you've made a friend here.
I'm still hoping
we'll have a chance
to celebrate
this new friendship together.
DREADNOUGHT:
All key systems
have been secured.
You will not gain access.
[PANTING]
I'm not interested in your
key systems anymore,
Dreadnought.
That is an unlikely
assertion, B'Elanna.
Seriously.
Check for yourself.
( console beeps )
You are attempting to access
the obsolete Cardassian file.
Why?
Oh, just killing time.
Life support
has been terminated.
It is advisable for you
to return to your ship.
Gentlemen,
I believe our best chance
at stopping Dreadnought now
is to set off
a large antimatter explosion
directly in its path.
To work, it would
take more energy
than all our photons
put together.
Or more to the point,
it would take
a warp core breach.
You'll be in charge
of the evacuation, Commander.
I'm not leaving you
on this ship.
Captain's prerogative.
Get the crew
to the escape pods.
I'll send
the senior officers
to join you
in a few minutes.
We don't have time
to debate this, Chakotay.
Everyone except
senior officers, with me.
Computer, initiate
the self-destruct sequence.
Authorization:
Janeway Pi 1-1-0.
Set it at 20 minutes.
COMPUTER:
Warning! Self-destruct sequence
has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in 20 minutes.
( beeping )
CARDASSIAN COMPUTER VOICE:
Cardassian ATR 4107
attempting to activate systems.
I never thought I'd be glad
to hear that voice again.
DREADNOUGHT:
Voice analyzer functioning.
Unable to identify.
CARDASSIAN COMPUTER:
Attempting to activate systems.
DREADNOUGHT: No additional
presence detected.
[PANTING] Check those
diagnostics, Dreadnought.
You're talking to yourself.
I believe you're having
an identity crisis.
CARDASSIAN COMPUTER:
Accessing central
processor memory.
DREADNOUGHT:
Engaging counter-virus
response program.
CARDASSIAN COMPUTER:
Attempting to override program.
Computer...
Identify the target.
CARDASSIAN:
Maquis munitions placed
on planetoid A-441.
DREADNOUGHT: The Cardassian
fuel depot on Aschelan V.
CARDASSIAN:
Malfunction detected
in the targeting system.
Attempting to correct.
DREADNOUGHT:
Negative. Target lock
has been confirmed.
The Maquis are now
in control...
This target doesn't conform
to established targeting
parameters...
The detonation sequence
cannot proceed without...
The countdown
to the detonation
sequence will continue.
Ejecting
antimatter pods.
Aschelan V
will be destroyed.
Emergency ejection
system has failed.
Attempting
to reinitialize
all key circuits.
Access
to the navigational
system is denied.
Accessing
backup system.
All critical pathways
have been rerouted
to protected backup systems.
Security lockouts
functioning...
( computer voices
overlap with glitches
and intermittent beeping )
( computer voices
continue overlapping )
( both computers beeping only )
Yes.
COMPUTER: Warning! Self-destruct
sequence has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in 11 minutes.
KIM: Captain, I've broken
through the interference.
I'm not sure how.
We have communications.
Checking on
transporter signal.
I have a lock on her.
Voyager to Torres.
TORRES: Yes, Captain.
I need
to get you out of there.
We're abandoning Voyager.
I'm going to overload
the warp core
in the missile's flight path.
I may be able to detonate
the warhead from here
by breaching
the containment field.
Can you get access
to the core?
I'm already in it.
I'm using my phaser
to burn through the magnetic
constrictor casing now.
( panting )
Are you all right,
B'Elanna?
Fine.
The air's just
a little thin in here.
Keep me advised.
Janeway out.
Mr. Kim, transfer
control to the comm,
and report
to your escape pod.
Captain...
That's a direct order
to all of you.
Mr. Paris, I'm
relieving you.
Now!
The starboard thrusters
are a little sluggish.
Ease into them.
Understood.
Captain...
Thanks for everything.
COMPUTER: Warning!
Self-destruct sequence
has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in seven minutes.
You, too, Tuvok.
It is logical to have
a second-in-command
in case you are injured
and unable to complete
the mission, Captain.
I request permission
to remain.
Permission granted.
DREADNOUGHT:
Hello, B'Elanna.
The Cardassian virus
has been neutralized.
Good for you.
Containment field
integrity at 40%
and falling.
Estimated time
to breach?
This vessel is programmed
to respond
with all necessary force
to prevent any disruption
to its mission.
Unless I'm mistaken,
you're out of options,
Dreadnought.
Analysis of your vital signs
suggests you are about to lose
consciousness, B'Elanna.
I'm not going anywhere
until I'm finished.
When you cease your efforts
to breach
the containment field,
life support will be restored.
No deal.
Warning! Self-destruct sequence
has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in three minutes.
Increasing velocity.
Preparing
to adjust our heading
to intercept.
Janeway to Torres.
Yes?
This is your last chance
to get back here, B'Elanna.
I have to launch
the last escape pods.
I understand, Captain.
I am almost finished.
Let me stay.
Warning! Self-destruct sequence
has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in two minutes.
DREADNOUGHT:
Containment field integrity
at 20% and falling.
Perhaps your
Delta Quadrant hypothesis
deserves
further consideration.
( labored chuckle )
Nice try.
Who would have thought,
two years ago,
after all those weeks
we spent together
perfecting your program...
that we'd end up out here...
trying to kill each other.
Probability assessment
did not anticipate
this outcome.
The missile's containment
field is collapsing.
Beam her back now.
Hang on.
Warning! Self-destruct sequence
has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in one minute.
Computer, terminate
self-destruct sequence.
Authorization:
Janeway Pi 1-1-0.
Confirmed.
Sequence terminated.
Janeway to Torres.
B'Elanna, are you...?
DR. ZIMMERMAN: She's here
in Sick Bay, Captain.
Please turn to your emergency
medical holographic channel.
Doctor, I forgot about you.
How flattering. I wanted
to advise you that I took
the liberty
of beaming Lieutenant Torres
from the Transporter Room
to Sick Bay.
She is somewhat singed
around the edges,
but should make
a complete recovery.
Very good, Doctor.
Janeway out.
Mr. Tuvok,
prepare to retrieve
our escape pods.
Let's bring
our crew home.
Aye, Captain.
( dramatic theme playing )
( dramatic
theme music playing )