Sorry I'm late,
but I have
a very good excuse.
Picture this:
I'm just getting ready
to leave the Mess Hall
when Ensign Wildman
goes into labor.
What else could I do
but deliver the baby?
Oh, you should
have been there, Harry.
There is nothing like bringing
a new life into the world.
I think I missed
my calling.
What if I told you
the turbolift got stuck
on Deck 6?
This is the third time
you've been late this week,
Mr. Paris.
It won't happen again.
TUVOK:
Commander,
I am picking up
a distress call
on one of the upper
subspace bands.
CHAKOTAY:
What's the source?
A small spacecraft.
No weapon systems.
One life-form aboard.
Extremely weak life signs.
CHAKOTAY:
Slow to half impulse.
According to
the bioscanner,
it's a Vidiian female.
Open a channel.
No response.
She may be too sick.
Or maybe it's
some kind of trick.
Preliminary scans show no other
Vidiian ships in this sector.
It is unlikely
that this is a trap.
Commander Chakotay,
notify the Doctor.
Mr. Kim, beam the woman
to Sick Bay.
KIM:
Aye, Captain.
Her renal organs
are functioning at
20 percent of normal
and her cardiovascular system
is on the verge
of collapse.
20 milligrams
of lectrazine.
Cardiovascular and renal
systems are stabilizing,
but her neural patterns
are fading.
What is it?
In her parietal lobe.
It looks like
some sort of implant.
It's a very complex web
of bio-neural circuitry,
nano-fibers.
Could this be
what's causing the problem?
On the contrary.
According to these readings,
the device is actually
storing her synaptic patterns,
processing them
and transmitting
neuro-electrical impulses
to the rest
of her systems.
Are you saying it's some kind
of artificial brain?
No.
I'd say it's more like
a neuro-cortical stimulator
designed to supplement
the higher brain functions.
But it's not
working anymore.
From what I can tell,
the implant itself
is functioning,
but it's connected
to mostly dead nerve cells.
If we don't do
something quickly,
she'll be brain dead
in a matter of minutes.
What about trying to
stimulate cell regeneration
with a high dosage
of inaprovaline?
Very impressive, Kes,
but I think it's
too late for that.
Get me a high-frequency
RF transmitter.
You're going to have
to hurry, Kes.
The patient's brain function
is diminishing rapidly.
Now... set the
delta band frequency
of the holo-emitter
to 8.6 tetrahertz.
What are we doing,
exactly?
Transferring the patient's
synaptic patterns
into the holo-buffer
before they degrade completely.
Is there enough
storage capacity
in the holo-matrix for such
complex data patterns?
There's enough capacity
for my program, isn't there?
And my program contains over
50 million gigaquads of data,
which, I don't have to tell you,
is considerably more
than the most highly-developed
humanoid brains.
What good is preserving
her synaptic patterns
if there is no body?
I'm creating
a holographic body.
Not only will we be able
to communicate
with the patient, but we'll
have an accurate model
of healthy Vidiian
physiology
that will aid
in treating
her actual body.
Computer, project the patient's
skeletal structure.
Now add internal organs.
Add musculature.
Now apply epidermal layers.
Computer,
use transporter records
to recreate
the patient's clothing.
( sighs )
[♪♪♪]
According to her ship's
navigational logs,
the woman was en route
to a remote Vidiian colony.
Are we anywhere near it?
It's about ten
light-years away.
We should be in the general
vicinity in about 22 days.
Assuming she survives
and we can take adequate
security precautions,
we'll turn her over to her
people when we get there.
Captain.
Is there something wrong?
I wanted to talk to you
about Lieutenant Paris.
His attitude lately's been
less than professional.
I've noticed.
I know crew discipline's
my responsibility,
but, in this case, I thought
I should let you get involved
before I took any action.
In a way, Paris has been
your personal
reclamation project.
I appreciate your bringing this
to my attention, Commander,
but I trust you to handle
the problem any way you see fit.
DOCTOR:
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Test results indicate
that the holographic body
is functioning normally.
The patient's synaptic patterns
appear to be stable,
so I'm now ready
to begin transferring
her cognitive
and motor processes.
Who are you?
I'm the Chief Medical Officer
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
We received your distress call
and brought you aboard.
What have you done to me?
It's quite
simple really.
I used the undamaged chromosomes
in your cerebellum
to recreate
your original DNA code,
and then programmed
the computer
to project
a holographic template
based on that genome.
Holographic?
A three-dimensional
projection
of light and energy.
See for yourself.
( gasps )
Your neural patterns
were degrading rapidly.
It was too late
to expect results
from inaprovaline,
so I was forced to improvise,
not that it would have occurred
to just any physician.
Why are you crying?
I'm sorry. I...
I thought you'd be pleased.
I am.
I just never expected
to look healthy again.
I've been sick for so long.
I'll need
a complete medical history.
How long have you
been ill exactly?
I was first diagnosed with
the phage when I was seven.
And when did you
begin receiving
replacement tissue?
About that same time.
At first, it was hard
to get used to the changes,
but it happened so often
that after a while,
I almost stopped noticing.
I-I never...
I never thought
I'd see myself again.
Thank you.
This is the most
extraordinary thing
anyone has ever done for me.
I wouldn't be too grateful.
There are serious limitations
to being a hologram.
First of all, we can only exist
within environments
equipped with holo-emitters,
such as this Sick Bay.
You mean, you're...
I'm this ship's emergency
medical holographic program.
You're a computer simulation?
An incredibly sophisticated
computer simulation.
I'm sorry.
What did you say your name was?
I don't have a name.
It wasn't part
of my original program.
However, you,
I'm sure, have one.
Danara.
Danara Pel.
Well, Miss Pel,
may I ask what someone
with an illness like yours
was doing alone in space
with no access to medical care?
I was helping to treat
an outbreak of the phage
on Fina Prime.
I was on my way
back to my home colony,
but it's a long journey
and my condition got worse.
You're a medical practitioner
of some kind?
A hematologist.
Well, then, perhaps,
given your expertise,
you can help me
with your treatment.
My treatment?
I feel fine.
Unfortunately, that's
only temporary.
Your synaptic patterns
will eventually degrade
if we don't get them out
of the pattern buffers
and back into your brain.
How long?
A few days.
Perhaps a week.
I see.
Your real body is in stasis.
As you can see,
we have to find a way
to repair your
damaged neural tissue.
( gasps )
Is something wrong?
It's nothing.
I'm eager to
discuss treatments.
Of course.
The procedure is quite simple.
I'll drill an opening
into your skull
precisely two millimeters
in diameter,
and then use a neuralyte probe
to extract a sample
of your parietal lobe
weighing approximately
one gram.
It doesn't sound simple to me.
I still have nightmares
about what those people
did to me.
And now you want
to crack open my head,
cut out a piece of my brain
and give it to her?
Your experience
in the Vidiian prison
suggests Klingon DNA
is resistant to the phage.
Losing a small amount of neural
tissue is inconsequential.
Not to me, it isn't.
Yet that same tissue,
grafted onto the patient's brain
and stimulated to grow,
will significantly
slow the spread
of her infection.
If we can increase the grafted
tissue mass quickly enough,
we can transfer
her synaptic patterns
back into her brain before they
degrade in the holo-buffer.
It won't cure the phage,
but it should
prolong her life considerably.
Please change
into a surgical gown
and lie down
on bio-bed number one.
I am not going...
Excuse me.
I just want to say that...
I've read about the experiments
that were done on you.
What you went through
must have been very traumatic.
That is an understatement.
I'm sure it is.
Please understand,
this disease
has been killing my people
for hundreds of years.
Trying to stop it
has become an obsession
and many of our politicians
and scientists
have never developed
compassion for the people
who keep us alive.
As much as I want
to go on living,
I have accepted the fact
that I will die soon.
I only want your help
if you are willing to give it.
Of course, I... I'd like
to help you if I can.
If you have any questions at all
about the procedure,
I'd... I'd be happy
to answer them for you.
( sighs )
I'll go and get changed.
DOCTOR:
I've finished
ingrafting
the Klingon
neural tissue
to your
cerebral cortex.
Now, all I have to do
is create
an axonal pathway
between that tissue
and your basal ganglia.
Your technique
is very impressive.
It's all part
of my programming.
For example, this exact
procedure was developed
by Dr. Leonard McCoy
in the year 2253.
I'm equipped with the collective
medical knowledge
of more than 3,000 cultures.
Additionally,
as you see here,
my imaging system
allows me to perform
and, in many cases,
improve upon
the most delicate
tactile maneuvers
required by
a dizzying array
of surgical procedures.
Incredible.
It is, isn't it?
Hand me the submicron
suture, please.
( instrument whirring )
There.
That should do it.
Ah. Excellent
work, Doctor.
I was only assisting.
Nonetheless,
that assistance was invaluable.
It could be
two or three days
before we'll know
if the graft will hold.
In the meantime, perhaps
I should deactivate
your program
temporarily.
Do you have to?
It would slow the degradation
of your synaptic patterns.
But I have
so much energy.
I don't know.
Maybe it's the excitement
of the surgery, or...
or maybe it's this new body.
What I'd really like to do
is take a walk
and see the rest of your ship.
Unfortunately,
that's not possible.
However, if you're looking
for something to do,
please feel free
to use my office
to access our medical database.
You'll find several
interesting texts
on comparative endocrinology.
All right.
Thank you.
On second thought,
there is someplace
else we could go.
( conversation, music
and laughter )
It's wonderful.
If I had a place
like this to go to,
I'd be there every day.
Don't your people have
recreational facilities?
Congregating
in groups
is strictly
regulated.
It's considered to be a
threat to public health.
A wise policy.
I suppose.
Sometimes, I think my
people spend so much time
trying to save lives,
they don't know
how to live anymore.
Doctor, aren't you going
to introduce me to your date?
She is not my date.
She's my patient.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize...
Mr. Neelix,
this is Dr. Danara Pel.
As Chief Morale Officer,
may I be the first
to welcome you to Voyager.
Madame, your loveliness
illuminates
our dark little cavern.
May I have the pleasure
of this next dance?
DOCTOR:
Go away immediately.
Both of you.
You're disturbing my patient.
You are just jealous
because you cannot dance.
Let's go.
You're making
the lady nervous.
Nice to meet you.
I apologize.
No. They were
just being nice.
Irritating, isn't it?
I guess I'm just not used
to... so much attention.
Where I come from,
when you're as sick as I am,
people, healthy people.
stay away from you.
I guess...
I...
I forgot for a second
that I don't look
like that anymore.
It's a natural response.
All this talk about me.
There's still so much
I'd like to know about you.
There's not much to tell,
really.
My program was developed
by Dr. Louis Zimmerman
in a lab on Jupiter Station.
I was activated
on stardate 48308.
Since that time, I've performed
347 medical exams,
healed 11 compound fractures,
performed three appendectomies
and, in my greatest feat
of medical prowess,
I once cured Mr. Neelix
of an acute case of the hiccups.
( laughing )
You're very funny.
I am?
Well, several clinical studies
have shown humor
to be very therapeutic.
Consider it
part of your treatment.
What is it?
It's, uh... just that I...
I haven't laughed
in a very long time.
Thank you.
What did that man mean
when he said you can't "dance"?
( accordion music continues )
That's dancing.
And you can't do it?
It's not part
of my programming.
Oh.
I see.
Well, Dr. Pel...
Please, call me Danara.
As you wish... Danara.
And what about you?
What should I call you?
Well, as I said--
I know.
You don't have a name.
Would it be all right
if I gave you one?
Well, I...
How about...
Shmullus?
It was my uncle's name.
He used to make
me laugh, too.
Doctor...
Shmullus.
I think I like
the sound of that.
( music continues )
Well...
here we are.
Yes.
Here we are.
Danara, I think we should--
Yes?
Deactivate your program
for at least eight hours.
If you think it's best.
I do.
All right, then.
All right.
Computer...
Shmullus?
Yes?
I had a wonderful time.
I'm pleased.
Thank you...
for...
everything.
Thank you for...
giving me a name.
Uh... well...
good night, Danara.
Good night...
Shmullus.
Computer,
deactivate Vidiian
program Alpha.
Mind if I join you?
So how are things, Tom?
Excuse me?
How have you been
feeling lately?
Is something bothering you?
Oh, no offense, Commander,
but why the sudden concern
for my feelings?
Well, you've been
moody lately,
indifferent to your duties.
To be honest, you
don't seem to be
taking your job
very seriously.
If you've got a problem,
I'd like to know
what it is.
Yeah, I've got a problem.
My problem is you.
You care to elaborate?
You tell me
I don't take my job seriously,
but half the time,
you don't let me do my job.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means that you
don't trust my judgment.
You don't allow me
to take initiative.
Remember last week?
I suggested
that we might save time
by traveling through
that emissions nebula.
But what did you say?
"Oh, no, that's not the way
we do things on this ship."
Look, sometimes I'm not going
to agree with your suggestions,
but making decisions
is part of being a leader.
Maybe someday you'll
understand that.
Being a leader also means
knowing when to give your people
a little leeway
and let them be creative.
We might as well put this ship
on autopilot
for all the freedom
you give me to do my job.
I didn't come here for a lecture
from you on how to do myjob.
Yeah, well, I know you don't put
much stock in my opinion,
so maybe you should talk
to some
of these people.
Because I'm not
the only one around here
who's got a problem with you.
Now, if there's nothing else...
sir...
I'd like to be excused.
Sure, Paris.
You're excused.
Dissension among
the Voyager crew.
Maje Culluh will find that
very interesting.
Good work, Mr. Jonas.
Now, there's something else
we'd like you to do.
We want you to create a small
accident, which will damage
Voyager's warp coils.
Why?
There's no need to concern
yourself with that.
You just... plan the accident.
We'll let you know
exactly when we want it
to happen.
Do we understand each other?
I want to talk to Seska.
I'm afraid Maje Culluh...
You tell Maje Culluh
that I won't do anything
to damage Voyager,
and if he has
a problem with that,
tell him to have
Seska contact me.
( cuts com contact )
Doctor, when you
have a minute.
I'm running a level-2
self-diagnostic right now.
I'll be there
as soon as I'm finished.
Why are you running
a diagnostic?
I've been experiencing
periodic lapses in concentration
and difficulty handling objects.
There may be a malfunction
in my tactile
acuity subroutine.
How long has this
been going on?
About two or three days.
Since Danara came aboard.
What's your point?
Maybe she's the reason
you're feeling this way.
I fail to see a connection.
Maybe you're attracted to her.
I told you,
my program's malfunctioning.
Romance is not a malfunction.
Romance is not part
of my programming.
Your programming's adaptive,
isn't it?
Yes.
Then I'd say it's adapting.
What if...
I don't want it
to adapt right now?
Why wouldn't you?
Because I don't like
what's happening to me.
I'm used to being in control
of my faculties...
confident of my decisions.
But lately...
whenever Danara's program
is deactivated
and I should be
concentrating on my work...
I find myself thinking
of nothing but her.
Why don't you
reactivate her?
Because whenever I do that,
I suddenly feel...
unsettled...
unsure of myself,
and I have no idea
what to say.
Why would people
seek out situations
which induce
such unpleasant symptoms?
Because when the other person
feels the same way you do,
it's the most wonderful
thing in life.
Suppose...
hypothetically
of course...
Of course.
I wanted to pursue
that possibility.
How would I proceed?
You'd have to tell her
how you feel.
That's it?
Just... tell her how I feel?
Otherwise, you may never know
how she feels.
I'm going to try stimulating
your motor neurons.
( instrument whirs )
Well, the nucleus cuneatus
appears to be functioning
normally.
And now for the anterior
thalamic pathway.
Excellent.
By the way, Danara, I've
been meaning to tell you...
Yes?
I'm romantically
attracted to you
and wanted to know
if you felt the same way.
Is something wrong?
No. I...
Did you understand what I said?
Yes.
Well?
Doctor, maybe now
isn't the time to...
Excuse me, Kes.
I was speaking to Danara.
I think it's best if we keep our
relationship... professional.
Well...
I'm going to...
try stimulating
the posterior sciatic nerve.
Doc, what brings you here?
Is somebody sick?
Actually, Mr. Paris,
I was looking for you.
Oh.
Well, pull up a chair.
Mr. Paris,
I assume you've had a
great deal of experience
being rejected by women.
Oh, thanks a lot, Doc.
What I'd like to know is:
What does one do to recover
from the unpleasant symptoms
of romantic rejection?
Why the sudden interest
in romance?
I can't tell you.
It's a matter of doctor/
patient confidentiality.
Ah.
All right, well, let's see.
Sometimes there's
not a lot you can do
to get over a woman
you really care about.
( chuckling )
I remember when Susie
Crabtree dumped me
back in my first year
at the Academy.
I broke out in hives.
Couldn't get out
of bed for a week.
I almost failed
Stellar Cartography.
I walked around
in a daze
for the rest
of that year.
Of course, the first one
is always the hardest
to get over.
I see.
But... eventually,
you start thinking
about her less and less,
until finally,
without realizing it,
she's not on your mind anymore.
So the symptoms do subside
over time?
For the most part.
But every now and then,
even years later,
something reminds you of her--
a certain smell,
a few notes of a song--
and suddenly you feel
just as bad as the day
she told you
she never wanted
to see you again.
If you want to know
the honest truth, Doc,
you never completely get over
a woman you really cared about.
Wait a minute.
Doc, we're not talking
about you, are we?
I told you, it was confidential.
Oh, boy, you've got it bad.
Look, Doc, I don't
mean to intrude,
but if you tell me what's
going on, maybe I can help.
( door opens, closes )
Hello, Kes.
Are you feeling
all right?
I'm fine.
I'm just... waiting
for the Doctor.
Oh.
He's been gone a long time.
You really like
him, don't you?
Then... why didn't
you tell him
that you felt the same way
when he told you that he
was attracted to you?
I don't know.
It all happened so fast.
He just blurted it out.
He's very blunt.
You shouldn't
take it personally.
How could he
possibly have
those kinds
of feelings about me?
Maybe because
you're a compassionate person,
a brilliant doctor,
you appreciate his humor...
Should I go on?
Please don't.
One thing you're
not very good at
is accepting
a compliment.
The next time
someone has
something nice to
say about you
maybe you should just
take them at their word
and feel good
about yourself.
It's not easy to feel
good about yourself
when you're used to living
your life... like that.
Danara, I can't
pretend to know
what your life's
been like,
but I do know
there's nothing sadder
than a missed
opportunity.
Maybe what you
and the Doctor need
is to spend some time
together... alone.
It sounds to me
like she might just be shy.
I think you
scared her off.
I did?
Your approach is all wrong.
Well, what would be
the right approach?
Women like romance.
They want men
to make an effort--
take them someplace special.
Where would I take her?
Come with me, Doc.
I've got an idea.
Doctor's Personal Log,
Stardate 49504.3.
Inaugural entry.
Kes and Mr. Paris
have conspired
to get Danara and me
alone together
in a place
Paris considers romantic.
I've never felt more... uneasy.
I wasn't sure
you were coming.
Neither was I.
If you don't want
to be here...
No.
I do.
Where are we exactly?
On a planet
called Mars.
Inside a primitive
land-based vehicle.
It's called a '57 Chevy.
Mr. Paris is quite
an automobile aficionado.
This is his program.
What is it that we're
supposed to be doing?
I believe it's
called... parking.
I almost forgot.
These are for you.
Thank you.
You're... you're
very... very thoughtful.
( The Platters
"My Prayer" plays )
♪ My prayer...♪
I downloaded a new
dancing subroutine
into my program
this morning.
Would you like
to get out and try it?
Actually...
I wouldn't mind just...
sitting here for a while.
You wouldn't?
Those moons
and star formations
are so different from anything
I've ever seen before.
Well, if you're
interested,
I could point out a few
astronomical highlights.
You see that bluish
planet there--
that's called "Earth."
It's where Starfleet
Headquarters is located.
♪ With the world far away...♪
And over... there
that's "Cygnus."
And there--
that constellation
is called "Hercules,"
named after a character
in ancient Greek myth.
Hippocrates
was also a Greek.
He was the father of...
♪ Tonight...♪
Earth medicine.
♪ While our heart are aglow...♪
And that cluster
over there--
that's... called
the "Pleiades."
♪ ...high ♪
♪ Sha bop sha bop ♪
♪ But I can't see a thing ♪
♪ In the sky ♪
♪ I only have eyes ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ I don't know if ♪
♪ We're in a garden ♪
Sorry I'm late.
That's all right, Mr. Paris.
We don't need you.
Mr. Grimes has taken
your place at conn.
But it's my shift.
Not today it isn't.
What, because I was
ten minutes late?
That's right.
Captain...
Don't look at me,
Mr. Paris.
Commander Chakotay has complete
discretion in this matter.
So, when should I
report back for duty?
When you decide to start
taking your job seriously,
we'll discuss it.
But right now,
you're dismissed.
Get your hands off me!
Mr. Tuvok.
Yes, Captain.
Please escort Mr. Paris
to the brig.
( com beep )
Oh, boy, am I glad to see you.
I wasn't even sure if they were
giving you my messages.
I've gotten them all, Mike.
You've been very helpful.
( sighs )
Do you know
what they're asking me to do?
You mean about the warp coils?
I was thinking you could do it
by forcing the magnetic
constrictors out of alignment.
Look, Seska, I don't mind
feeding you information,
but if you're planning
some kind of attack...
I have no intention of raising
my child on a Kazon ship!
One way or another,
I'm going to take Voyager.
You can either help me
or you can suffer
along with Janeway
and the others.
Don't worry, Mike.
Everything's been planned
to the letter.
Here's how it's going to work.
We'll be waiting for you
on a planet called Hemikek IV.
Doctor's Personal Log,
Stardate 49507.2.
The more time I spend
with Danara,
the more my programming
continues to adapt.
I look forward to perfecting
my romantic skills
once we've completed
the synaptic transfer.
Set the delta
band frequency
of the holo-emitter
to seven terahertz.
Seven terahertz.
( tricorder beeping warning )
Wait a minute.
Did you administer the cervaline
as I instructed?
500 milligrams
every four hours.
I don't understand it.
What's wrong?
The brain-- your brain--
it's rejecting the graft.
We can't go through
with the transfer.
I'm detecting elevated
levels of nytoxinol.
Where could that
have come from?
Is it possible
you made an error?
Administered nytoxinol
instead of cervaline?
No, I don't think so.
But here's
the hypospray I used.
Check for yourself.
You're correct.
It's cervaline.
Has anyone else
been in Sick Bay
during the last 24 hours
other than you and Danara?
Crewman Foster came
in for some analgesic
and Ensign Wildman
was here
for her regular
prenatal visit. Why?
Because, if the nytoxinol was
not administered by accident,
I can only conclude
that someone is deliberately
trying to kill Danara.
Who would want to kill her?
Perhaps someone who bears
ill will toward Vidiians.
Whoever it is,
I intend to find out.
I'm calling
Lieutenant Tuvok.
Please don't do that.
We have to find out
who's trying
to obstruct your recovery.
Iadministered
the nytoxinol.
Didn't you know
it would kill you?
You mean kill her.
She is you.
Was me.
I don't ever want
to be her again.
What are you doing?
Looking for the cervaline.
I have to reduce the rate
of tissue rejection
before it's too late.
Kes, would you excuse us?
I don't want to go through
with the transfer.
If we don't get
your neural patterns
out of the holo-buffer,
you'll be brain dead
in a matter of days.
I can't let that happen.
I'd rather live two more
days like this with you
than go on for who
knows how long,
wasting away a piece
at a time.
It's my duty
to keep you alive.
I thought you were
more than my doctor.
I thought you
were my friend.
I amyour friend.
What kind of friend
would ask me
to go on living
like this?
And for what?
So that I can go back to a world
where everyone I ever
loved has died,
where almost everyone
I meet is going to die?
You're a doctor.
You can help them.
I can't
help them.
I can't cure them.
All I can do
is prolong their suffering...
just like you want
to do to me now.
Danara...
I have no desire
to see you suffer.
Do you know what
it's like? Do you?
No, but...
What it's like to be
a nine-year-old child
and suddenly your best friend
doesn't want to come
to your house anymore.
And when you ask
your mother why...
"Why won't Mala come
and play with me anymore?"
And she tells you
it's because...
it's because the other children
are afraid of you.
( sighs )
Listen to me.
Before I met you,
I was just a disease.
But now, everything's different.
When people look at me,
they don't see
a disease anymore.
They see a woman,
a woman you made,
a woman you love,
a woman you're not
afraid to touch.
Danara, I was never
afraid to touch you.
Why? Because
you're a doctor?
Because I love you.
You say that now,
but if I go through
with the transfer...
If you go through
with the transfer...?
I will be sick again...
and ugly.
Danara, you're not ugly.
You're simply ill.
( sighs )
Please, stop patronizing me!
I know how people see me.
Danara, do you think
if you go back
into your own body,
I'll feel different
about you?
Won't you?
Listen to me.
Nothing could
ever change
the way I feel about you--
not a few scars,
not some diseased skin, nothing.
You have given me
the most extraordinary gift
that anyone has ever given me.
You brought me to this ship
where no one is sick,
and people are friendly.
You've made me
healthy and beautiful.
I don't want to go back
to the way things were.
You said, before you knew me,
that you were just a disease.
Well, before you, I was just
a projection of photons
held together by force fields,
a computerized physician
doing a job,
doing it exceptionally well,
of course,
but still, it was... just
a profession, not a life.
But now that you're here,
and my programming has adapted,
I'm not just working anymore.
I'm living,
learning what it means...
to be with someone,
to love someone.
I don't think
I can go back
to the way things
were either.
Danara, please...
don't die.
I want us to be together.
So do I.
But if you put me back
into that body,
I'll have to go home...
and help my people.
I know.
But we'd still have
two weeks together
before we reached
your colony.
Danara, please,
be with me
for as long as you can.
Computer, play music program
Doctor-alpha.
( waltz playing )