GOOD DAY, VOYAGER,
AND WELCOME TO
A BRIEFING WITH NEELIX.
IT'S A CATCHY TITLE, ISN'T IT?
I'LL BE COMING TO YOU
EACH AND EVERY DAY
WITH NEWS OF GENERAL INTEREST,
INTERVIEWS WITH
OUR FASCINATING CREW MEMBERS,
MUSICAL PERFORMANCES,
RECOMMENDATIONS
FOR NEW HOLODECK PROGRAMS
AND, OF COURSE,
PREVIEWS OF UPCOMING MEALS--
EVERYTHING FROM HLAKA SOUP
TO ZABEE NUTS.
A BRIEFING WITH NEELIX
WILL HELP YOU STAY INFORMED
ABOUT SHIP'S ACTIVITIES,
UH, KEEP YOU ABREAST OF
YOUR COLLEAGUES' ACCOMPLISHMENTS
AND BROADEN YOUR KNOWLEDGE
ABOUT A WEALTH OF SUBJECTS.
BUT MOST OF ALL,
IT WILL MAKE YOU FEEL GOOD,
BECAUSE WHAT YOU SEE HERE
WILL ALWAYS BE
THE MOST UPLIFTING,
OPTIMISTIC VIEW
OF EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENS ON OUR SHIP.
AFTER ALL,
AS YOUR MORALE OFFICER
ISN'T IT MY JOB
TO BRING A LITTLE JOY
INTO EVERYONE'S DAY, HMM?
CAPTAIN JANEWAY HAS AGREED
TO APPEAR ON THE SHOW
WITH REGULAR UPDATES
ABOUT THE SHIP'S PROGRESS,
AND COMMANDER CHAKOTAY WILL
COMMEND OUTSTANDING CREW MEMBERS
SO, SNAP TO, AND KEEP THOSE
BOOTS POLISHED TO A SHINE.
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHEN YOU MIGHT BE FEATURED
ON A BRIEFING WITH NEELIX.
READY, ENSIGN?
Ensign: ALL SET, NEELIX.
IN JUST A MOMENT,
AN AMAZING TALENT.
ENSIGN PABLO BAYTART
WILL ASTOUND YOU
WITH HIS JUGGLING ABILITY.
HE'LL KEEP PADDS, HYPOSPRAYS,
EVEN PHASERS IN THE AIR
FOR MINUTES AT A TIME.
I DON'T... BUT BEFORE THAT,
WHAT MAKES PEOPLE FEEL BETTER
THAN A LITTLE ROMANCE?
AND WHAT LIEUTENANT
IN A GOLD UNIFORM
WAS RECENTLY HUDDLED
IN THE MESS HALL
WITH WHAT CREWMAN IN BLUE,
HAVING A VERY INTIMATE
CONVERSATION
OVER A CARAFE OF SILMIC WINE?
WELL, I'D NEVER NAME NAMES,
BUT YOU KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
BEST WISHES
TO A HANDSOME PAIR OF LOVEBIRDS.
AND NOW...
ladies and gentlemen,
Ensign Pablo Baytart.
WELL? WHAT DID YOU THINK?
I'M A DOCTOR,
NOT A PERFORMER.
I DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR SUCH NONSENSE.
I CAN SEE
"HINTS FOR HEALTHFUL LIVING"
BECOMING A VERY POPULAR
SEGMENT, DOCTOR.
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU'D BE LIFTED TO
A WHOLE NEW LEVEL
IN THE CREW'S EYES.
THEY'D HANG ON YOUR EVERY WORD.
YOU'D ENJOY A POPULARITY,
A CELEBRITY
THAT YOU'VE NEVER KNOWN BEFORE.
I WOULD?
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO ANSWER RIGHT AWAY.
JUST THINK ABOUT IT, OKAY?
AH! MR. KIM!
JUST THE PERSON
I WANTED TO SEE.
SEE YOU LATER.
DID YOU WATCH
A BRIEFING WITH NEELIX
THIS MORNING?
UH, YES. YES, I DID.
IS THERE SOMETHING
ABOUT THE PROGRAM YOU DISLIKED?
I'M NOT SURE I CARE
FOR ALL THE FROSTING.
FROSTING?
DECK FOUR.
RECIPES, MUSIC, JUGGLERS--
IT'S SORT OF LIKE A
STEADY DIET OF DESSERT,
WHICH IS FINE,
BUT PRETTY SOON,
YOU WANT SOME MEAT
AND POTATOES.
YOU DO?
WHEN I WAS IN SCHOOL
I WAS EDITOR OF THE ACADEMY
NEWSPAPER FOR A YEAR.
I MONITORED SUBSPACE
TRANSMISSIONS.
I GOT REPORTS ON SOME
OF THE FIRST ACTIVITY
BY THE MAQUIS AGAINST
THE CARDASSIANS.
I WROTE AN EDITORIAL
ABOUT IT,
AND THE STUDENTS BECAME
POLARIZED ON THE ISSUE.
THEY DEBATED THE
PROS AND CONS
AND GAINED AN INSIGHT
INTO THE ENTIRE HISTORY
OF THE POLITICAL REBELLION.
NOW, THAT'S THE
POWER OF JOURNALISM.
WHAT DID YOUR PROFESSOR SAY
WHEN YOU TOLD HIM
YOU WERE GOING
TO PUBLISH THE EDITORIAL?
I DIDN'T TELL THEM.
IT'S THE JOB OF A JOURNALIST
TO BE INDEPENDENT.
Woman:
Bridge to Mr. Neelix.
You have
an incoming transmission.
I'M HEADING FOR MY QUARTERS.
PUT IT THROUGH THERE.
Yes, sir.
Neelix, my friend, how are you?
LAXETH, YOU OLD
DILITHIUM SCRUBBER!
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
CALLING TO TRADE ME
SOME OF YOUR
ILL-GOTTEN GOODS AGAIN?
I PROMISE YOU
I NEVER WANT TO SEE
ANOTHER WHEEL
OF PENDRASHIAN CHEESE.
Oh, those days are behind me.
I'm legitimate now.
I'm Communications Master
of a Talaxian convoy.
COMMUNICATIONS MASTER...
WELL, YOU'VE CERTAINLY
COME UP IN THE WORLD.
CONGRATULATIONS.
Looks like I'll be seeing you
in a few days.
HOW'S THAT?
We've been asked
to rendezvous
with your ship.
We're going to pick up
a passenger.
PASSENGER?
WE DON'T CARRY ANY PASSENGERS.
Apparently,
it's a member of your crew.
All I know is
someone wants to leave your ship
and come to work for us.
JUST HOW, EXACTLY, DID YOU HEAR
THAT SOMEONE
WAS LEAVING THE SHIP?
AN OLD FRIEND OF MINE IS SERVING
WITH A TALAXIAN CONVOY.
HE TOLD ME
THEY'D BE RENDEZVOUSING WITH US
IN A FEW DAYS.
JANEWAY TO TUVOK.
Yes, Captain?
COULD YOU JOIN US IN
MY READY ROOM, PLEASE?
Right away.
LIEUTENANT, MR. NEELIX HAS HEARD
ON GOOD AUTHORITY
THAT ONE OF OUR CREW
WILL BE LEAVING THE SHIP
IN A FEW DAYS.
NATURALLY,
HE'S CURIOUS
ABOUT THE IDENTITY
OF THIS PERSON.
WHAT ARE THE SECURITY
ISSUES HERE?
I DON'T BELIEVE THERE ARE
ANY SERIOUS CONCERNS, CAPTAIN.
THERE IS NO NEED TO WITHHOLD
THIS INFORMATION ANY LONGER.
LIEUTENANT PARIS...
HAS ASKED TO BE
PUT OFF THE SHIP.
TOM?
I'M SURE YOU'RE AWARE
THAT HE'S HAD SOME
PROBLEMS LATELY.
WELL, YES.
Tuvok:
HE HAS BEEN DISRUPTIVE,
AND OFTEN SETS A BAD EXAMPLE
FOR THE REST OF THE CREW.
BUT... HE SEEMED SO DETERMINED
TO GET THOSE THINGS BEHIND HIM.
IT MEANS A LOT TO HIM
TO BE RESPECTED BY THIS CREW.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU IS THAT
WHEN HE WAS RELIEVED OF DUTY,
HE ASKED ME TO MAKE ARRANGEMENTS
FOR HIM TO LEAVE THE SHIP.
I TRIED TO TALK HIM OUT
OF IT, BUT HE WAS ADAMANT.
WE DETECTED THE
TALAXIAN CONVOY
AND THEY WERE MORE
THAN HAPPY TO GET A
PILOT OF TOM'S ABILITY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
I NEVER THOUGHT...
CAPTAIN, MAY I SPEAK WITH HIM?
OF COURSE.
HE'S IN HIS QUARTERS.
( door chimes )
COME IN.
HELLO, TOM.
NEELIX. HOW'S IT GOING?
NOT GOOD, IT LOOKS LIKE.
WHAT'S WRONG?
I HEAR YOU'RE LEAVING THE SHIP?
GOOD NEWS TRAVELS FAST, I GUESS.
YEAH, I FIGURED THERE WAS
QUITE A BIT MORE OPPORTUNITY
FOR ADVANCEMENT
ON A TALAXIAN CONVOY
THAN THERE WAS
ON THE ONLY STARFLEET SHIP
IN THE QUADRANT.
WHEN DID YOU MAKE
THIS DECISION?
TRUTHFULLY? UH, ABOUT
A MINUTE AND A HALF
AFTER I SET FOOT
ON THIS SHIP A YEAR AGO.
I KNEW IT WAS A MISTAKE TO TRY
TO FIT INTO STARFLEET AGAIN,
AND I SHOULD HAVE LISTENED
TO MYSELF.
A FEW MORE MONTHS
IN THAT REHAB COLONY
WOULD HAVE BEEN
A HELL OF A LOT BETTER
THAN BEING HERE.
TOM, YOU AND I HAVE
HAD OUR DIFFERENCES
BUT I THOUGHT WE PUT
THOSE BEHIND US. I...
I JUST HOPE I HAVEN'T...
CONTRIBUTED TO YOUR DECISION.
NEELIX, NO.
THIS ISN'T ABOUT ANYBODY
EXCEPT ME.
I'VE DONE THIS TO MYSELF
JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
NO MATTER WHERE I GO
OR WHO I'M WITH,
I MAKE A MESS OF THINGS.
THE UNMISTAKABLE CONCLUSION
HAS TO BE THAT DEEP DOWN
I DON'T WANT ANY FRIENDS
OR A FAMILY OR A HOME.
OTHERWISE,
I WOULDN'T KEEP SABOTAGING
THE POSSIBILITIES.
I THOUGHT YOU FOUND
THOSE THINGS HERE.
I TRIED,
OR MAYBE
I JUST TOLD MYSELF I WAS TRYING.
I'M NOT SURE.
EITHER WAY,
IT'S JUST NOT WORKING.
FRANKLY, I'D LIKE TO GET OUT
BEFORE I COMPLETELY DESTROY
MY IMAGE.
THERE MIGHT ACTUALLY BE
ONE OR TWO PEOPLE
WHO STILL HAVE
A GOOD OPINION OF ME.
I'M ONE OF THEM, TOM...
AND I WISH YOU WOULDN'T GO.
WELL, I THANK YOU...
BUT, THE TRUTH IS
I'VE ALWAYS
CONSIDERED MYSELF A DRIFTER.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THAT'S LIKE, NEELIX.
FREEDOM TO DO WHAT YOU WANT,
WHEN YOU WANT.
NO RULES TO FOLLOW,
NOBODY DEPENDING ON YOU, RIGHT?
Doctor:
Well, there you are.
I've been waiting
for what seems like hours.
DOCTOR, WHAT CAN
I DO FOR YOU?
I want to discuss the details
of my participation
on your program.
I've been giving it
a great deal of thought
and I've come up
with a number of ideas
I think you'll find quite
intriguing.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
I'M DELIGHTED YOU'VE DECIDED
TO BECOME A CONTRIBUTOR.
BUT I'M AFRAID I DON'T HAVE TIME
TO DISCUSS IT RIGHT NOW.
But I've already prepared
today's topic:
"How To Keep
Your Nostrils Happy."
THAT IS FASCINATING.
BUT I'M AFRAID
THERE'S A MORE IMPORTANT STORY
I HAVE TO WORK ON TODAY.
You mean...
I'm not going to appear today?
WHEN YOU SEE IT,
I'M SURE YOU WILL UNDERSTAND.
Hmm. But I will be on tomorrow?
DEFINITELY.
WITHOUT FAIL, I PROMISE YOU.
Very well, but tomorrow,
I'll want to cover two topics.
I have a most entertaining idea.
"Uncovering the Hidden Mysteries
of the Adrenal Gland."
FINE, FINE. GOODBYE, DOCTOR.
GOOD MORNING, VOYAGER.
I WANT TO TELL YOU
ABOUT A FRIEND OF MINE.
I FIRST MET THIS MAN
ALMOST A YEAR AGO
AND, TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I DIDN'T LIKE HIM MUCH.
HE SEEMED A LITTLE TOO COCKY,
A LITTLE TOO SURE OF HIMSELF.
A lot of people had questions
about him.
He'd proven he'd pretty much
sell himself out
to the highest bidder,
go wherever the wind blew him.
So people wondered,
could you trust this person
when things got tough?
Would he stand
side by side with you,
or would he let you down
when you needed him most?
But the fact of the matter is
he proved himself
right from the beginning.
I wouldn't be alive right now
if it weren't for him.
And the same goes
for many of you.
It took me a while
to realize it.
Like a lot of people,
I was too caught up
in first impressions
to see the truth
that was right in front of me.
I overlooked his bravery because
I was focusing on his brashness.
I ignored his courage
because I saw it as arrogance
and I resented his friendliness
because I mistook it
for licentiousness.
So while this man
was giving us his best
every minute of every day,
I was busy judging him.
AND NOW, HE'S LEAVING.
I'M PROUD TO SAY THAT IN SPITE
OF MY NARROW-MINDEDNESS
THOMAS EUGENE PARIS
BECAME MY FRIEND.
I'M GOING TO MISS HIM.
NO MORE LAUGHS
OVER A GAME OF POOL.
NO MORE SITTING UP
INTO THE WEE HOURS
SWAPPING STORIES.
NO MORE COMPLAINTS
ABOUT MY COOKING.
( chuckling )
GOODBYE, TOM.
I THINK I SPEAK FOR MORE OF US
THAN YOU MIGHT IMAGINE
WHEN I SAY
YOU'RE GOING TO LEAVE  AN EMPTY
SPACE WHEN YOU GO.
I HOPE YOU FIND
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
OPERATIONS HAS DETECTED
A MINUTE INCREASE
IN THE ENGINE CORE TEMPERATURE.
ARE YOU AWARE OF IT?
YES, CAPTAIN. THERE'S A SLIGHT
IMBALANCE
IN THE MAGNETIC
CONSTRICTORS.
IT'S CAUSING THE PLASMA
STREAM TO OVERHEAT.
I HAVE A TEAM
WORKING ON IT.
KEEP ME POSTED.
MR. NEELIX, I'M VERY
PLEASED WITH YOUR PROGRAM
ESPECIALLY YOUR TRIBUTE
TO LIEUTENANT PARIS.
THANK YOU.
CAPTAIN, HAVE YOU DECIDED
WHO'S GOING TO REPLACE PARIS?
I HAVE SEVERAL PEOPLE IN MIND.
BAYTART IS ONE. HAMILTON.
CAPTAIN, DO YOU THINK..?
I MEAN, IT'S POSSIBLE TOM MIGHT
CHANGE HIS MIND, TO COME BACK.
MAYBE YOU SHOULDN'T
REPLACE HIM SO QUICKLY.
HARRY, LIEUTENANT PARIS
MADE HIS DECISION
WITH NO INDICATION THAT HE HAD
ANY DOUBTS ABOUT IT
OR THAT HE MIGHT CHANGE
HIS MIND IN THE NEAR FUTURE.
WE HAVE TO ACCEPT
THAT AND MOVE ON.
WHAT'S OUR
TACTICAL STATUS?
ALL SYSTEMS ARE FUNCTIONAL.
Jonas:
Engineering to Torres.
GO AHEAD.
We have a problem here.
WHAT IS IT?
THE MAGNETIC CONSTRICTORS
HAVE LOST ALIGNMENT.
THE PLASMA STREAM
IS WAY TOO HOT.
IT'S STARTING TO INFECT
THE INJECTOR VALVES.
I'M ON MY WAY.
WE'RE FINISHED
HERE. DISMISSED.
LIEUTENANT, IF I MAY...
THIS SOUNDS LIKE NEWS
OF SUBSTANCE TO ME.
JUST STAY OUT OF OUR WAY.
IT'S GOTTEN WORSE.
I CAN'T GET
THE INJECTOR VALVES CLOSED.
ANTIMATTER IS STARTING TO SEEP
INTO THE WARP CORE.
HAVE YOU TRIED ADJUSTING
THE POWER TRANSFER CONDUITS?
YES. NO EFFECT.
WE HAVE TO TRY TO CONTAIN
THE REACTION IN THE CORE.
DON'T LET THE P.T.C. TEMPERATURE
GET ABOVE 3.2. MILLION KELVINS.
IT'S AT 2.9 MILLION NOW.
( high-pitched whine )
P.T.C. TEMPERATURE NOW
AT THREE MILLION KELVINS.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO VENT SOME PLASMA.
IF YOU VENT PLASMA THAT HOT
THROUGH THE NACELLES
THE WARP COILS
ARE GOING TO FRY.
BETTER THAT THAN A CORE BREACH.
REINFORCE THE STRUCTURAL FIELD
AROUND THE POWER
TRANSFER CONDUITS,
AND THEN PREPARE
TO BEGIN VENTING PLASMA.
P.T.C. TEMPERATURE NOW
3.2 MILLION KELVINS!
IT'S CASCADING.
GET AWAY FROM THAT CONSOLE.
I CAN STOP IT FROM HERE.
GET AWAY, JONAS!
( Jonas groaning )
COMPUTER,
INITIATE PLASMA VENTING.
ARE WE ALL RIGHT?
P.T.C. TEMPERATURE
IS DROPPING.
APPROACHING SAFE LEVELS.
WE'RE UNDER CONTROL.
NEELIX TO SICK BAY.
PREPARE FOR
EMERGENCY TRANSPORT.
WE HAVE THREE WOUNDED.
THIS ONE'S NOT BADLY HURT.
20 MILLIGRAMS IMPEDRAZINE.
VITAL SIGNS STEADY.
SECOND DEGREE BURNS
TO FACE AND CHEST.
TREAT HIM WITH
THE DERMAL REGENERATOR.
THE SITUATION
HAS BEEN STABILIZED.
NONE OF THE VICTIMS
IS IN DANGER ANY LONGER.
MAY I INTERVIEW
ONE OF THEM NOW?
ONE OF THE PATIENTS?
I'D THINK YOU'D BE
MORE INTERESTED
IN MY ASSESSMENT
OF THE MEDICAL SITUATION.
WELL, I AM, OF COURSE.
WOULD YOU CARE
TO MAKE A STATEMENT?
YES.
THE FIRST TASK IS TO TRIAGE
OR TO ASSESS
THE RELATIVE CONDITION
OF EACH OF THE VICTIMS,
AND THEN TO PRIORITIZE
TREATMENT ACCORDINGLY.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
I'M SURE THAT WILL BE OF GREAT
INTEREST TO THE CREW.
I WASN'T FINISHED.
NEXT, THE TREATMENT, PER SE,
MUST BE SUPERVISED.
VERY INTERESTING.
NOW, I KNOW THE CREW WOULD
LOVE TO HEAR A FEW WORDS
FROM THE MAN
WHO RISKED HIS LIFE
TO SAVE THE SHIP.
WOULD YOU CONSENT
TO AN INTERVIEW?
I WAS JUST DOING
MY JOB, NEELIX.
LIEUTENANT TORRES IS
THE ONE YOU SHOULD TALK TO.
Janeway to Neelix.
RIGHT HERE, CAPTAIN.
Could you join us
on the bridge, please?
I'M ON MY WAY.
I'LL CONTACT YOU LATER
ABOUT THE INTERVIEW.
THE PLASMA BURST IRRADIATED
THE ENGINE NACELLES.
THE INNER LAYER OF
THE WARP COILS WAS BURNED AWAY.
WHICH MEANS
THE WARP ENGINES ARE USELESS
UNTIL WE CAN REBUILD THEM.
THEY'RE MADE
FROM A SUBSTANCE
KNOWN AS VERTERIUM
CORTENIDE.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE WE
CAN FIND A SOURCE?
VERTERIUM CORTENIDE.
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN
THAT'S A DENSIFIED
COMPOSITE MATERIAL.
THAT'S RIGHT. IT'S COMPOSED
OF POLYSILICATE VERTERIUM
AND MONOCRYSTAL CORTENUM.
DO YOU KNOW
OF ANY NEARBY SOURCE?
LET'S SEE.
THERE'S A YELLOW DWARF
SYSTEM CALLED HEMIKEK
WITH AN M-CLASS PLANET
QUITE RICH IN MINERALS.
MINING RIGHTS BELONG
TO A CONSORTIUM OF
NONAGGRESSIVE PEOPLE.
I'M SURE WE COULD
MAKE ARRANGEMENTS
TO PURCHASE SOME
VERTERIUM AND CORTENUM.
GOOD WORK, NEELIX.
CAPTAIN, MESSAGE COMING IN
FROM THE TALAXIAN CONVOY.
PUT IN ON SCREEN.
Laxeth: Captain Janeway...
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
We were attacked
by the Kazon-Nistrim.
DO YOU HAVE CASUALTIES?
HOW CAN WE HELP?
We have no serious casualties,
and they didn't take
any of our cargo.
The one thing
they were interested in
was your former crewman,
Thomas Paris.
They took him aboard their ship
and then left.
I thought you'd want to know.
TOM PARIS...
HELLO, SESKA.
YOU'RE LOOKING
RADIANTLY MATERNAL.
IN ANOTHER MONTH,
CHAKOTAY WILL HAVE A SON...
OR A DAUGHTER.
I REALLY DIDN'T
WANT TO KNOW WHICH.
MAKES IT MORE INTERESTING,
DON'T YOU THINK?
I WOULDN'T KNOW.
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHICH ONE CHAKOTAY WOULD PREFER.
HE AND I RARELY SEE
EYE TO EYE.
YOU'VE HAD YOUR PROBLEMS
WITH HIM LATELY TOO.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
YOUR SUDDEN INABILITY
TO BE STARFLEET'S GOOD BOY.
IT'S NOT SUDDEN.
I NEVER REALLY FIT IN THERE.
THEN "LIEUTENANT TOM PARIS"
WAS JUST A PRETENSE.
NO.
NO, IT WAS ME TRYING VERY HARD
TO BE SOMEONE
I FINALLY COULDN'T BE.
I NEVER LIKED YOU, TOM.
I DIDN'T TRUST YOU.
I DON'T TRUST YOU NOW.
I CAN ASSURE YOU
THE FEELING IS MUTUAL.
FINE.
BUT WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP EACH OTHER...
IF YOU'RE TELLING THE TRUTH.
IS THAT WHY YOU KIDNAPPED ME
AND DRAGGED ME HERE
SO WE CAN BE PALS NOW?
I THOUGHT
IT MIGHT MAKE SENSE TO YOU.
AND IF IT DOESN'T?
THE KAZON TEND TO BE EXCESSIVE
IN THEIR USE OF FORCE.
IT'S NOTHING I CAN CHANGE.
BUT I CAN PROMISE
YOU'LL BE WELL-TREATED
ON THIS SHIP
IF WE DECIDE
WE CAN WORK TOGETHER.
WHAT EXACTLY WOULD THAT MEAN?
YOU'RE AN EXCELLENT PILOT.
WE COULD MAKE GOOD USE
OF YOUR SKILLS
AND, OF COURSE, YOU HAVE
INFORMATION ABOUT VOYAGER
THAT COULD BE QUITE VALUABLE.
IT SEEMS TO ME
LIKE YOU'RE ALREADY GETTING
A LOT OF VALUABLE INFORMATION
ABOUT VOYAGER FROM SOMEWHERE.
THINK ABOUT IT, TOM.
THINK ABOUT
WHERE YOU WANT TO BE
WHEN THE NISTRIM
SEIZE VOYAGER
AND START TAKING CONTROL
OF THE QUADRANT
SECTOR BY SECTOR.
JUST LET ME KNOW.
CAPTAIN'S LOG, STARDATE 49485.2.
IN SPITE OF THE FACT
THAT TOM PARIS
HAS BEEN ABDUCTED
BY THE KAZON,
WE MUST CONTINUE ON COURSE
FOR THE HEMIKEK SYSTEM.
SOMETHING JUST DOESN'T MAKE
SENSE.
I MEAN, HE WASN'T OFF THE SHIP
FOR A DAY WHEN THE KAZON
ATTACKED THAT CONVOY.
HOW DID THEY FIND
OUT SO FAST THAT TOM WAS THERE?
MAYBE SOMEONE ON THE CONVOY
TOLD THEM?
A TALAXIAN CONVOY
WOULD NEVER LET THE KAZON
KNOW WHERE THEY ARE.
THAT WOULD BE LIKE COMMITTING
SUICIDE.
MAYBE THEY CAME
TO ROB THE CARGO
BUT WHEN THEY REALIZED
THERE WAS A STARFLEET OFFICER...
THAT WOULDN'T HAVE STOPPED THEM
FROM TAKING THE CARGO TOO.
AND ACCORDING
TO MY FRIEND, LAXETH,
IT WAS A SWIFT,
EFFICIENT STRIKE.
IT SOUNDS LIKE
THEY KNEW TOM WAS THERE
AND THEY CAME
JUST TO GET HIM.
BUT WHO WOULD HAVE
TOLD THEM?
ONE POSSIBILITY I CAN THINK OF
IS THAT IT WAS SOMEONE
ON THIS SHIP.
ON VOYAGER?
WHO WOULD DO THAT?
I DON'T KNOW...
BUT A RESPONSIBLE JOURNALIST
WOULD FIND OUT.
B'ELANNA, I DIDN'T EXPECT
TO FIND YOU HERE.
ARE YOU WORKING
THE NIGHT SHIFT?
I HAVE BEEN
SINCE THE ACCIDENT.
WHAT BRINGS YOU HERE?
I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU COULD SHOW ME
HOW TO ACCESS THE SUBSPACE
COMMUNICATIONS LOGS?
WHY WOULD YOU
BE INTERESTED
IN THE COM LOGS?
WELL, JUST PART
OF MY NEWS PROGRAM.
WELL I CAN GET YOU INTO THEM,
BUT THEN YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
I'M STILL TRYING TO BRING
THE MAGNETIC CONSTRICTORS INTO
ALIGNMENT.
I UNDERSTAND.
JUST GET ME STARTED.
HOW FAR BACK
DO YOU WANT TO GO?
OH, MAYBE A MONTH OR TWO.
OKAY, THE FILE'S OPEN.
TRANSMISSIONS ARE LOGGED
BY DATE AND TIME.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, I'LL BE FINE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MIKE, WE'RE GOING
INTO THE COMPUTER CORE
TO LOOK OVER THE
CONSTRICTOR CIRCUITRY.
HOLD DOWN THE FORT, ALL RIGHT?
OKAY, LIEUTENANT.
VOYAGER TO MITHREN.
MITHREN AGAIN.
VOYAGER TO KOTATI...
WERE YOU LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING
IN PARTICULAR?
I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT I'M LOOKING FOR.
SOMETHING ANOMALOUS.
WHY?
AN INCIDENT I'M INVESTIGATING.
TELL ME, MR. HERO,
IF SOMEONE WANTED TO MAKE
A SECRET SUBSPACE TRANSMISSION,
HOW WOULD HE DO IT?
WHY WOULD YOU WANT
TO KNOW THAT?
I CAN'T BE TOO FORTHCOMING
RIGHT NOW,
BUT IF I FIND
WHAT I THINK I'M GOING TO,
WELL, LET ME JUST SAY
THAT THIS SHIP
WILL BE STUNNED.
A SECRET TRANSMISSION, HUH?
WELL, THAT WOULD BE TOUGH,
NEELIX.
THERE ARE ALL KINDS OF
SECURITY ROUTINES IN PLACE,
AND ANY TIME A SUBSPACE
ANTENNA ARRAY IS IN USE,
THE SENSORS MAKE
A RECORD OF IT.
I'M NOT SEEING ANYTHING
ANOMALOUS HERE.
WHAT ABOUT THAT?
WHAT?
THAT... GAP.
AS IF SOME OF THE LOG ENTRIES
HAVE BEEN DELETED.
WELL THAT'S JUST A DATA
FRAGMENTATION.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
IT PROBABLY HAPPENED
WHEN THE PLASMA
OVERLOADED THE SYSTEM.
LITTLE GLITCHES LIKE THIS WILL
BE POPPING UP FOR WEEKS, I'D
IMAGINE.
HERE IT IS AGAIN.
I WOULDN'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
MAYBE LIEUTENANT TORRES
CAN EXPLAIN IT.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO EXPLAIN.
BELIEVE ME, NEELIX,
YOU'RE MAKING TOO MUCH OF IT.
Neelix:
AH, HERE IT IS AGAIN.
GAPS IN THE LOG ENTRIES.
AND FRANKLY, IT LOOKS LIKE MORE
THAN DATA FRAGMENTATION TO ME.
THE GAPS ARE SHOWING UP
IN LOGS
ENTERED OVER
THE LAST MONTH,
BUT NOT BEFORE THAT.
Doctor:
So there you are!
I've been looking for you,
Mr. Neelix.
DOCTOR, HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
You again neglected to include
me in your news program.
If you remember, I was to have
two segments today
because I was excluded
yesterday.
THAT'S RIGHT, THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE BEEN SO PREOCCUPIED
WITH THIS OTHER MATTER.
In the interest of time,
I'm willing to forego
my story on the adrenal gland.
I will concentrate instead
on my latest idea
"The Klingon Glottis:
Friend or Foe?"
THAT'S VERY INTERESTING,
BUT WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO PUT
IT OFF UNTIL TOMORROW.
That's what you said yesterday.
I'M SORRY, DOCTOR,
BUT I REALLY HAVE TO GO NOW.
Neelix:
ALL THROUGH
THE SUBSPACE COMMUNICATION LOGS,
THERE WERE THESE GAPS,
AS THOUGH SOMETHING
HAD BEEN ERASED.
WE HAVE RECENTLY
EXPERIENCED
A PLASMA OVERLOAD.
THAT COULD
EASILY ACCOUNT
FOR THE ANOMALOUS
READINGS IN THE LOGS.
AHA! I KNEW YOU'D SAY THAT.
ANSWER THIS, MR. VULCAN:
WHY WOULD THOSE GAPS,
THOSE DELETIONS
OCCUR ONLY
IN THE SUB COM LOGS
AND ONLY IN THE LAST MONTH?
I CHECKED
EVERY LOG SYSTEM WE HAVE--
SENSOR LOGS,
POWER ALLOCATION LOGS,
WARP MAINTENANCE LOGS,
ENVIRONMENTAL CONTROL LOGS.
THEY'RE ALL PERFECTLY FINE.
WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING?
I BELIEVE SOMEONE ON THE SHIP
HAS BEEN MAKING
COVERT TRANSMISSIONS
AND ERASING THE EVIDENCE.
TO WHAT END?
I DON'T KNOW,
BUT I SUSPECT WHOEVER IT WAS
HAS BEEN COMMUNICATING
WITH THE KAZON.
THAT'S
AN EXTREMELY SERIOUS CHARGE.
I KNOW.
THAT'S WHY I'VE COME TO YOU.
MR. NEELIX, I STRONGLY SUSPECT
THAT YOUR ENTHUSIASM
FOR YOUR NEW
JOURNALISTIC ENDEAVOR
IS LEADING YOU TO SEE VILLAINS
WHERE NONE EXIST.
HOWEVER, EVEN THE
POSSIBILITY THAT SOMEONE
ON BOARD MIGHT SECRETLY
BE COMMUNICATING WITH THE KAZON
DESERVES INVESTIGATION.
I WILL PURSUE
THE MATTER.
AND I WILL HELP YOU.
I THINK NOT.
THIS IS NOW A MATTER
OF SHIP SECURITY.
I MUST ASK YOU TO WITHDRAW
AND LET ME HANDLE IT
ACCORDING TO
STARFLEET PROTOCOLS.
AS A JOURNALIST, I HAVE
AN ETHICAL OBLIGATION
TO KEEP DIGGING
FOR THE FACTS IN THIS CASE.
AND I HAVE THE
HIGHER OBLIGATION
TO KEEP YOU FROM PUTTING
YOURSELF AND OTHERS AT RISK.
YOU WILL DROP THIS MATTER.
I SEE.
ALL RIGHT. I LEAVE IT
IN YOUR HANDS.
GOOD HUNTING.
"A HIGHER OBLIGATION"?
HA. I'LL SHOW HIM
HIGHER OBLIGATION.
HE'LL HAVE ESKARIAN EGG
ON HIS FACE
WHEN I GET TO THE HEART OF THIS.
IT'S THE JOB OF A JOURNALIST
TO BE INDEPENDENT.
LIEUTENANT, I WONDER
IF YOU COULD...
I'M A LITTLE BUSY
RIGHT NOW, NEELIX.
WHAT DO YOU NEED?
I WAS WONDERING
IF IT'S POSSIBLE TO
LOOK UNDERNEATH A LOG
THAT SEEMS
TO HAVE BEEN ERASED,
SEE IF THERE'S
ANYTHING LEFT OF IT.
MR. HOGAN, COULD YOU PLEASE
HELP NEELIX OUT FOR A MINUTE?
YOU WANT TO RECOVER
DELETED LOGS?
UH, THAT WOULD BE IDEAL.
WELL, LET ME
GIVE IT A TRY.
USUALLY IT'S POSSIBLE
TO RECOVER DATA
UNLESS EXTRAORDINARY
MEASURES
WERE TAKEN TO ERASE IT.
WELL, THIS IS STRANGE.
COMPUTER, RUN A SIGNAL
MODULATION ANALYSIS
OF THIS FILE.
Security authorization required.
ENGINEERING AUTHORIZATION
OMEGA FOUR-SEVEN.
Authorization accepted.
Running analysis.
WHAT?
I... CAN'T RECOVER THE LOGS,
BECAUSE THESE MESSAGES WERE SENT
WITHOUT USING
ANY OF THE ANTENNA ARRAYS.
HOW COULD SOMEONE DO THAT?
BY SENDING THE
TRANSMISSIONS
THROUGH THE SHIP'S POWER GRID.
THE MESSAGES WERE ENCODED
IN THE WASTE ENERGY
FROM THE PROPULSION SYSTEMS,
WHICH IS
ALMOST INDISTINGUISHABLE
FROM GALACTIC BACKGROUND NOISE.
INGENIOUS.
WOULD THERE BE A WAY
TO DETERMINE
WHO SENT THE MESSAGES?
I'M LOOKING
FOR SIGNAL CORRELATION TRACES.
THEY'D INDICATE A COM LINK
TO THE E.P.S. CONDUITS--
MAYBE GIVE US A LOCATION.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN...
THERE.
THERE'S ONE.
THE SOURCE OF
THE COM LINK
IS ON DECK FOUR,
SECTION THREE-C.
SORRY, BUT I CAN'T GET
MORE SPECIFIC THAN THAT.
MR. HOGAN, I NEED
YOUR HELP OVER HERE.
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP.
I'LL CHECK OUT DECK FOUR.
GO ROOM BY ROOM,
CONSOLE BY CONSOLE.
I'D LOOK FOR EVIDENCE
OF RECENT DELETIONS.
IF YOU SEE ANY,
RUN A RECOVERY PROGRAM.
SEE WHAT YOU GET.
COMPUTER, ACTIVATE MONITOR.
Unable to comply.
Monitor is cleared for
Lieutenant Thomas Paris only.
OVERRIDE EXISTING CLEARANCE.
ENGINEERING AUTHORIZATION
OMEGA FOUR-SEVEN.
Authorization accepted.
Files recovered.
UNBELIEVABLE.
MY FRIENDS,
I DERIVE NO SATISFACTION
FROM WHAT
I AM ABOUT TO TELL YOU.
I KNOW I ORIGINALLY PROMISED YOU
THAT I
WOULD ONLY BRING YOU GOOD NEWS.
HOWEVER, I FEEL IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT YOU KNOW THE TRUTH.
I HAVE UNCOVERED EVIDENCE
THAT CASTS SERIOUS DOUBT
ON THE LOYALTIES
OF LIEUTENANT THOMAS PARIS.
I have discovered secret
communications to the Kazon
that were sent from his quarters
just prior
to his leaving the ship.
GET HIM UP HERE... NOW.
There was a series of messages
sent to the Kazon
for some weeks before his
departure...
HOW DID YOU TRACE THOSE
TRANSMISSIONS TO TOM'S QUARTERS?
IT WAS, UH...
I BELIEVE IT WAS CALLED
SIGNAL CORRELATION TRACES.
MR. HOGAN WAS HELPING ME
AND HE DETECTED THEM.
WHEN I LOOKED FOR
SIGNAL CORRELATION TRACES
THERE WERE NONE.
THAT MEANS SOMEONE PLACED
THEM IN THE SYSTEM
AFTER MY INITIAL
INVESTIGATION.
WHAT INITIAL INVESTIGATION?
CAPTAIN, WHAT'S GOING ON?
( sighing )
WHAT I'M ABOUT TO SAY WILL COME
AS A SURPRISE TO YOU, COMMANDER.
THERE HAS BEEN A
SPY ABOARD VOYAGER
BUT IT ISN'T TOM PARIS.
IT ISN'T?
NO. LIEUTENANT PARIS IS,
IN FACT, PART OF OUR PLAN.
PLAN?
SOME WEEKS AGO, TUVOK
DISCOVERED EVIDENCE
OF COVERT TRANSMISSIONS
LEAVING VOYAGER THROUGH
THE E.P.S. SYSTEM.
WE REALIZED THERE WAS
SOMEONE ON THIS SHIP
COMMUNICATING WITH
THE KAZON-NISTRIM.
Tuvok:
HOWEVER, WE WERE UNABLE TO
ASCERTAIN WHO THAT PERSON WAS.
WE NEEDED A WAY
TO FLUSH OUT THE SPY
AND WE HAD EXHAUSTED
ALL CONVENTIONAL MEANS.
THAT'S WHEN
WE THOUGHT OF USING TOM
FINDING A WAY TO GET HIM
ON THE KAZON SHIP.
ARE YOU SAYING PARIS'
INSULTING BEHAVIOR
THE GAMBLING,
BEING LATE FOR DUTY
MOUTHING OFF AT ME,
WAS ALL A RUSE?
THAT IS CORRECT.
IT WAS IMPORTANT THAT
HIS DECISION TO LEAVE THE SHIP
APPEAR PLAUSIBLE, SO HE BEGAN
BEHAVING LIKE A MALCONTENT.
AND THE REASON I WASN'T LET IN
ON THIS LITTLE PLAN?
I WAS THE ONE
WHO RECOMMENDED
TO CAPTAIN JANEWAY
THAT YOU NOT BE TOLD.
I SUSPECTED THAT THE SPY
WAS A MAQUIS
AND FELT IT WAS WRONG
TO PUT YOU IN A POSITION
OF SETTING A TRAP FOR SOMEONE
WHO HAD ONCE SERVED UNDER YOU.
IN OTHER WORDS,
YOU DIDN'T TRUST ME.
COMMANDER, THE
SIMPLE FACT IS
WE NEEDED A
GOOD PERFORMANCE.
I'M AFRAID WE USED YOU
TO HELP TOM PROVIDE IT
AND YOU DID A
DAMN GOOD JOB.
NOW, IT SEEMS MR. NEELIX'S
INVESTIGATION
HAS MADE SOMEONE NERVOUS--
NERVOUS ENOUGH
TO PUT A TRAIL
IN THE COMPUTER SYSTEM
FOR HIM TO FOLLOW.
COULD IT BE HOGAN?
I DON'T THINK SO.
HE WAS JUST THE PERSON
WALKING BY
WHO LIEUTENANT TORRES
ASKED TO HELP ME.
THE SPY MAY BE
A LITTLE COZY NOW
SINCE YOU TOOK THE BAIT
AND POINTED THE FINGER AT TOM,
BUT WE DON'T
WANT HIM COZY.
I'D RATHER HE
FEEL SOME PRESSURE.
PERHAPS WE SHOULD
TAKE ADVANTAGE
OF MR. NEELIX'S
UNINTENTIONAL BLUNDER.
EXACTLY. I WANT YOU
TO KEEP INVESTIGATING, NEELIX.
DO WHAT YOU'VE BEEN DOING--
POKE AROUND, ASK QUESTIONS--
BUT LET PEOPLE THINK
YOU'RE NOT SO SURE
YOU WERE RIGHT ABOUT TOM PARIS.
THAT WOULD PUT NEELIX IN A
POTENTIALLY DANGEROUS SITUATION.
WE WOULD KEEP AN OPEN
COM LINK TO YOU, AT ALL HOURS.
MY SECURITY TEAM
COULD ACT IMMEDIATELY
IF ANYTHING
WERE TO HAPPEN.
IT'S UP TO YOU, NEELIX.
THIS IS PURELY VOLUNTARY.
ANYTHING I CAN DO
TO HELP, CAPTAIN
AND GET TOM HOME SAFELY,
I WANT TO DO.
( static )
What did you expect?
Do you think
this has all been
about exchanging
holiday greetings?
No, of course
not, but...
Here's how it is going to work.
We'll be waiting for you
on a planet
called Hemikek Four.
( static )
WELL, TOM, IT'S ALWAYS GOOD
TO HAVE ONE'S
INSTINCTS VERIFIED.
CLEVER PLAN, SESKA.
LEADING VOYAGER
INTO AN AMBUSH
BUT EVEN SO, THIS SHIP WILL BE
OUTMANNED AND OUTGUNNED.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE
GROUND TROOPS ON HEMIKEK
AND MORE SHIPS
ON THE WAY.
NOW, DON'T YOU WISH
YOU'D TAKEN MY OFFER?
( mechanical whine )
THANKS FOR THE HOSPITALITY.
GO GET HIM.
LIEUTENANT TORRES IS WAITING FOR
THESE INTERLINK SEQUENCERS.
GET THEM TO HER
RIGHT AWAY.
EXCUSE ME.
OH, HELLO, NEELIX.
I WAS WONDERING IF ONE OF YOU
COULD HELP ME?
WE'RE A LITTLE BUSY RIGHT NOW.
WHAT IS IT THAT YOU NEED?
THE SIGNAL
CORRELATION TRACES
THAT IMPLICATED
TOM PARIS--
THEY WERE ADDED
TO THE FILE AFTER THE FACT.
YOU'RE KIDDING?
SO, I WAS TRYING
TO FIGURE HOW
THAT COULD HAVE HAPPENED
AND WHO MIGHT HAVE DONE IT.
THIS COULDN'T BE
A WORSE TIME, NEELIX.
WE'RE GETTING EVERYTHING READY
FOR REBUILDING THE WARP COILS.
DO YOU MIND IF I USE
THE DIAGNOSTIC TERMINAL
OVER THERE?
GO AHEAD.
JUST DON'T TAP INTO
ANY ENGINEERING SYSTEMS.
I'LL BE CAREFUL.
Torres to Engineering.
JONAS HERE, LIEUTENANT.
I need the electrodynamic
load specs.
They weren't with
the other things you sent.
SORRY, LIEUTENANT. I'LL GET THEM
TO YOU RIGHT NOW.
TAKE THESE
TO LIEUTENANT TORRES.
RIGHT.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
Janeway:
Bridge to Engineering.
JONAS HERE, CAPTAIN.
I need you to increase
transporter range.
Shunt all available power
TO TRANSPORTER ROOM TWO.
Right away.
LET ME KNOW AS SOON
AS YOU'VE DONE IT.
WE HAVE AN INCOMING SHUTTLE,
AND WE'VE IDENTIFIED
HUMAN LIFE SIGNS.
It may be Tom Paris.
YES, MA'AM.
PARIS TO VOYAGER!
DO YOU READ ME YET?
Paris to Voyager! Come in!
VOYAGER TO PARIS. WE HEAR YOU.
CAPTAIN, CHANGE YOUR COURSE
IMMEDIATELY.
THE KAZON HAVE GROUND TROOPS
WAITING FOR YOU
on Hemikek,
and more ships on the way.
WE'LL GET YOU OUT OF THERE AS
SOON AS WE CAN TOM.
YOU'RE STILL OUT
OF TRANSPORTER RANGE,
BUT WE WON'T CHANGE COURSE UNTIL
WE'VE LOCKED ON TO YOU.
I CAN TAKE CARE
OF MYSELF!
Just get Voyager to safety!
As soon as you're on board.
TOM, WHAT HAPPENED?
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
Lieutenant Paris, report.
MR. JONAS,
WE NEED THAT TRANSPORTER NOW.
I'm working on it, Captain.
I'M HAVING TROUBLE RESETTING
THE E.P.S. MANIFOLD.
Janeway:
Stay on it.
MR. JONAS, I'M NO EXPERT,
BUT IT DOESN'T LOOK TO ME
LIKE YOU'RE WORKING
ON THE TRANSPORTER
SUBSYSTEMS.
NEELIX,
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
( electrical crackling )
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WHAT IS THIS FORCE FIELD FOR?
IT'S JUST A PRECAUTION.
PLEASE, NEELIX!
STAY OUT OF THIS!
Janeway:
Tom, can you hear me? Report.
I'M HERE, CAPTAIN.
We'll be
in normal transporter range
in another minute.
CAPTAIN... THE SPY.
IT'S MICHAEL JONAS.
He's the one
that sabotaged the ship.
NOTED. JANEWAY TO TUVOK.
GET TO ENGINEERING
IMMEDIATELY.
IT'S MICHAEL JONAS.
Tuvok:
On our way.
SHUTTLE HULL
STARTING TO BREACH.
MIGHT NOT MAKE IT, CAPTAIN.
I RECOGNIZE THAT SUBROUTINE.
YOU'RE INTO
THE WEAPONS SYSTEM.
YOU'RE DISABLING THEM!
FOR GOD'S SAKES,
NEELIX, BACK OFF.
NEELIX TO...
( groans )
WE'RE IN TRANSPORTER
RANGE, CAPTAIN.
VOYAGER TO PARIS.
Tom, can you hear me?
We're energizing now.
TRANSPORTER ROOM TWO,
DO YOU HAVE HIM?
We have him, Captain.
He's all right.
IT'S THE KAZON SHIP, CAPTAIN.
RETURN FIRE. JANEWAY TO TUVOK,
ARE YOU IN ENGINEERING YET?
The doors are sealed.
We're working on it, Captain.
BRIDGE TO TRANSPORTER
ROOM TWO.
LOCK ON TO MR. JONAS
IN ENGINEERING
AND BEAM HIM OUT OF THERE.
Man:
Aye, Captain.
All I got
was his combadge, Captain.
CAPTAIN,
WE'VE LOST WEAPONS.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE PHASER
ARRAYS HAVE BEEN DISABLED
FROM ENGINEERING.
EVASIVE MANEUVERS, ENSIGN.
MR. KIM, GET THOSE WEAPONS
BACK ON-LINE.
( grunts )
( groaning )
( yelling )
( bellowing )
WEAPONS ARE BACK
ON-LINE, CAPTAIN.
FIRE AT WILL.
YES, MA'AM.
ARE YOU INJURED?
DON'T WORRY ABOUT ME,
MR. VULCAN.
I'M PERFECTLY ALL RIGHT.
UNFORTUNATELY, MR. JONAS
WASN'T SO LUCKY.
Janeway:
Bridge to Tuvok.
I'm standing down Red Alert.
WELL, I'M GOING TO HAVE
PLENTY OF MATERIAL
FOR TOMORROW'S
BRIEFING WITH NEELIX.
...AND FORTUNATELY,
I WAS ABLE TO STEAL
ONE OF THE KAZON SHUTTLES
AND ESCAPE.
AN AMAZING STORY.
AMAZING.
NOW, I'D LIKE TO SAY
SOMETHING MORE, IF I MIGHT.
OF COURSE.
UM, I KNOW THAT I'VE
BEEN ACTING LIKE A JERK
FOR THE LAST COUPLE OF MONTHS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
I HAD TO BEHAVE THAT WAY
IF THE SPY
WAS GOING TO BELIEVE
THAT I REALLY WANTED
TO LEAVE THE SHIP.
SO I'D LIKE TO APOLOGIZE
TO ANYONE
THAT I MIGHT HAVE OFFENDED...
UH, ESPECIALLY
COMMANDER CHAKOTAY.
I GAVE HIM A PRETTY HARD TIME.
NOT THAT IT WASN'T A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF FUN, MIND YOU.
( hearty laugh )
THERE YOU HAVE IT,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THE TRUE HERO
OF THIS WHOLE ENDEAVOR:
LIEUTENANT
THOMAS EUGENE PARIS.
WELL, I'M AFRAID THAT'S
ALL THE TIME WE HAVE.
OH, I'D LIKE TO
APOLOGIZE TO THE DOCTOR
FOR NOT GETTING AROUND
TO HIM ONCE AGAIN TODAY.
BUT I PROMISE YOU,
HE'LL BE HERE TOMORROW
WITH LOTS OF FASCINATING
INFORMATION
ABOUT THE BOLIAN
DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
GOOD DAY, VOYAGER.