Good afternoon,
Ensign.
How are we
doing today?
We're doing just
fine, thank you.
Good, good.
By the way, I was wondering
if you'd take a look
at the thermal array
in the kitchen.
It overloaded
this morning
and vaporized
an entire pot roast.
I'd be happy to.
Wonderful.
I informed Ensign Kim
about the problem hours ago
and he still hasn't
come down to fix it.
He's been working
on a problem
with the structural
integrity grid.
I'm sure he hasn't
forgotten about you.
If this thing doesn't
get fixed soon
we'll all be eating
cold leftovers for dinner,
and who do you think
the crew will blame?
Looks like you need a new set
of anodyne relays.
( grunts )
I'll go down
to Engineering
and get some for you
out of storage.
Thanks.
Oh, and while you're here,
would you mind taking a look
at the replicator?
It's been having
trouble making anything
with large amounts
of cellulose.
Of course.
Cabbage, syllium,
green beans, celery--
it all comes out
looking a touch
too yellow.
I thought you didn't
use replicated vegetables
when you're cooking.
Always fresh, organic,
from the aeroponic bay?
Well, the yields have been
a little low lately.
Normally, I would never dream
of using synthesized veggies.
It looks like a malfunction
in the power grid.
Shouldn't be
too difficult...
( gasping )
What's wrong?
I think I'm having
a contraction.
Oh, yeah. It's a
contraction, all right.
That's wonderful.
Labor can't be far behind.
Let-Let's get you
to Sickbay.
Try to breathe now.
Deep, deep, regular breaths.
Not so fast now.
We're having a baby.
Aw!
Push!
( gasping )
Don't forget to
breathe, Samantha.
Deep, regular breaths.
That's it.
Cervical dilation is
at 10.2 centimeters.
Prostaglandin levels
are normal.
Push, Ensign!
You push, damn it!
I'm sick of pushing!
I know you're
fatigued.
Try to focus on
your breathing.
Remember the
exercises we did.
When you feel a
contraction, bear down.
( sighs )
This is ridiculous.
It's been seven hours.
How long does it take
to deliver a baby?
As long as it takes,
Mr. Paris.
TUVOK: Indeed.
During the birth of
our third child,
my wife was in labor
for 96 hours.
Four days?
I have learned that pregnancy
and patience go hand-in-hand.
You know, I didn't
expect to be this nervous.
It's not even my child.
In a way, this child
belongs to all of us.
It is the first baby
born on Voyager.
I'm just not sure whether
I should be welcoming it
on board or apologizing.
Captain?
Voyager isn't exactly
anyone's idea of a nursery
and the Delta Quadrant
isn't much of a playground.
My father had a
saying, Captain.
"Home is wherever
you happen to be."
TUVOK:
Captain, long range sensors
are picking up heavy subspace
communications ahead.
They're Vidiian.
All stop. A ship?
At least 20 ships
within sensor range.
I am also detecting
a G-type star system
with two inhabited planets.
Lifesigns... Vidiian.
Sounds like we're headed
right into their territory.
And I'm in no mood to
donate any organs today.
Options,
Mr. Paris.
There's a large plasma drift,
bearing 4-0 mark 7.
It extends almost half
the length of this sector.
The interference from
the plasma should block us
from their sensors.
Good thinking. Lay in
a course at full impulse.
Mr. Tuvok, deflectors
at maximum.
( gasping )
( straining )
Oh!
Oh, what was that?
What's wrong?
A pain... in my abdomen.
It's different... sharp.
Oh, God!
The baby has
shifted position,
and its exocranial
ridges have lodged
in the uterine wall.
This is a rare
complication,
but it's been
known to happen
in human-Ktarian
pregnancies.
Can we reposition
the baby?
No, its spinal
column is too fragile.
I don't want to
risk nerve damage.
( groaning )
If we don't deliver
the baby now,
its ridges could
perforate the uterus
and cause internal
bleeding.
Kes, prepare for
fetal transport.
We're clearing the
Vidiian system, Captain.
Take us out of
the plasma drift
and resume our
previous course.
DR. ZIMMERMAN:
I've locked onto
the baby's coordinates.
We're ready to begin.
Initiating
umbilical separation.
Energizing.
( crying )
( exhales )
Congratulations, Ensign.
It's a girl.
( crying loudly )
Is she all right?
The transport caused a slight
hemocythemic imbalance,
but we'll stabilize
her cell membranes
with osmotic pressure therapy.
( rumbling )
What was that?
We hit some kind of
subspace turbulence
as we were coming out
of the plasma drift.
I can't tell if...
What the hell?
Captain, the warp engines
just stalled.
Go to impulse.
Impulse engines
aren't responding.
Maneuvering thrusters
are out too.
We're losing main power.
Switching
to backup power.
Red Alert.
Bridge to Engineering.
Report!
Our antimatter supply
is being drained, Captain.
I don't know why.
The containment fields
are in place.
It's like we sprung a leak,
but I can't find the crack.
B'Elanna,
try infusing the warp core
with repeated proton bursts.
That should be enough
to keep it going.
I think I can generate enough
protons in the sensor array
for a burst every 30 seconds.
Do it.
Hogan, these proton bursts
are going to cause a lot of
stress on the hull.
Reinforce structural
integrity to...
( low booming )
Now what?
What was that?
It appeared to
be a proton burst.
Already?
Bridge to Torres, report.
Engineering, respond.
Captain, three E.P.S. conduits
just ruptured in Engineering.
They took heavy casualties.
The incubator is losing power.
( baby crying )
Activate the auxiliary
respirator.
We've got wounded here!
( people groaning )
( dramatic
theme music playing )
Second-degree plasma burns
on the face and neck.
Treat him with
the dermaline gel.
Fractured clavicle,
thoracic contusions.
Nothing serious,
she can wait.
Fused vertebrae,
prep him for surgery.
Status.
It doesn't look good, Doctor.
The baby's cell membranes
won't stabilize.
Increase the
osmotic...
( low booming )
That's not helping.
Increase the osmotic
pressure ratio by 10%.
KIM:
Bridge to Sick Bay.
There's been a major
coolant leak in the mess hall.
You've got more
wounded on the way.
Acknowledged.
Torres to Bridge!
We're definitely...
( grunts )
We're definitely being
hit by proton bursts,
but I don't know where
they're coming from.
I never even started
the procedure.
She's right. The main sensor
array is off-line.
Not a single burst was fired.
Yet the bursts appear
to be originating from
within the ship--
it's like they're coming
out of thin air.
Captain, these bursts
are weakening
the structural integrity of the
hull; we cannot take any more.
Can we increase power
to structural reinforcement?
KIM: Our antimatter
supply is too low.
There's just not
enough power to go...
Hull breach on Deck 15,
Section 29 Alpha.
Emergency force fields
are off-line.
Captain,
I've been working on a way
to enhance our portable
force field generators.
It might be enough to seal
that breach.
Go.
NEELIX:
Don't you worry.
We have the best
doctor in the quadrant.
Doctor, her cell membranes
are losing cohesion.
Try remodulating
the osmotic pressure.
No effect.
Hang on, I'll
be right there.
Oh, no.
Jefferies Tube 12 runs
right over the breach.
If we can get close enough,
we should be able
to set up a portable
containment field.
The breach has weakened the
integrity of that tube by 22%.
That's why we need
to reinforce the field.
We'll use the power
conduits on this deck.
( grunting )
Go!
I've analyzed the bursts
on all spectral frequencies.
There's still no indication
of where they're coming from.
At this point, I don't give a
damn where they're coming from.
I just want to stop them.
Chakotay, do we have
enough auxiliary power
to magnetize the hull?
It might cushion the
impact of the bursts.
We have just barely enough.
Give it a try.
I've stabilized
my imaging array
but it could go out
at any time.
Doctor...
Prepare for emergency
resuscitation.
My baby, she...
She's going to die,
isn't she?
Not if I can help it.
Here it is. The breach
is directly below us.
Make it fast, Harry.
Torres to Hogan.
What's your status?
Almost got it, Lieutenant.
I'm rerouting all power
in this section to your...
( low booming )
( screams )
Torres to Hogan.
Hogan, are you there?
Ugh, I'm hurt...
Hurry, we have
to help him.
Just give me a minute.
( machine beeping )
DR. ZIMMERMAN: Again!
( monitor flatlining )
Nothing.
I'm sorry, Ensign.
( crying )
( groans )
Hogan to Sick Bay.
I need... medical assistance.
Deck 15, Section 29.
I'll go.
( sobbing )
The breach is widening.
Let's get out of here.
Damn it, Harry,
let's go!
Hold on.
My minute isn't
up yet...
Agh!
Harry!
Grab my hand!
( gasping )
KES:
Lieutenant Hogan!
TORRES:
Kes, over here!
Torres to Bridge.
Ensign Kim is dead.
Kes just disappeared.
Disappeared?
I can't explain it.
She just vanished.
There seems to be
some kind of spatial rift
right where
she disappeared.
Can you determine
where it leads?
Stand by, Bridge.
I just threw a piece
of conduit into the rift.
Just as it vanished,
I detected another
oxygen/nitrogen atmosphere.
Another atmosphere?
Whatever's on
the other side of that rift
there's air--
maybe Kes is still alive.
( low booming )
Get out of there, Torres.
The hull breach is widening.
I'm going to evacuate
the entire deck.
You don't have
to tell me twice.
The main computer core
is failing.
Switching to backup processor.
( grunts )
Chakotay, are you ready
to magnetize the hull?
Standby. I'm having trouble
with the alignment module.
Try remodulating
the field emitter.
( all grunting )
Chakotay.
I've got alignment.
Magnetizing the hull.
I think it worked.
Let's hope so.
I want a full damage report
from all decks.
Are you all right, Captain?
It's just a scratch.
It's more than a scratch,
maybe should go...
I'm fine, Lieutenant.
TUVOK:
Damage reports are coming in.
The hull breach
on Deck 15 has widened
to include Deck 14, Section 12.
And there are
632 micro-fractures
along the hull's
infrastructure.
All primary systems
are off-line.
We are running
on emergency power only.
The antimatter supply
has dropped to 18%
and is continuing
to fall.
Warp coils in both nacelles
have fused and are inoperative.
The environmental control
systems are failing.
15 crew members
have been seriously wounded
with plasma burns.
27 experienced
other injuries.
The doctor is setting up
triage facilities
in Sick Bay
and Holodeck Two.
I must also regretfully report
that Ensign Wildman's baby
did not survive.
I want an engineering team
to seal those micro-fractures
before they become breaches.
TUVOK: Aye, Captain.
Mr. Paris, grab
a medical tricorder
and go assist the doctor.
Right.
Commander, you have the Bridge.
I'm going to go talk
to Ensign Wildman.
Maybe I can help...
MAN: Hold on...
( grunting )
The magnetic field
is collapsing.
The hull is depolarizing.
The fire suppression
system is out!
COMPUTER: Warning!
Hull breach on Deck One.
Emergency force fields
inoperative.
Everybody out!
Go! Go! Go!
Hurry, Captain!
I'm trying
to reroute emergency power
to the field emitters!
Captain!
I can seal this breach!
Captain, let's go!
Captain?
Ensign Kim,
scan the Bridge.
I just saw myself
cross the Bridge
and enter that turbolift.
It was very faint--
almost like a ghost image,
and I looked like hell.
Captain, there was
a minor spatial fluctuation
on the Bridge,
but it was only there
for a millisecond.
Bridge to Engineering.
B'Elanna, how long
until we can use
the main sensor array?
Another three hours.
We're only
about halfway through
the proton burst
procedure.
See if you can speed up
the process.
We need the sensors
as soon as possible.
Understood.
Mr. Kim,
modify a tricorder
to scan for spatial anomalies.
Go over every centimeter
of this Bridge.
Examine the sensor logs
from our trip through
the plasma drift.
Look for
anything unusual.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
Aye, Captain.
Good news, Ensign.
Our baby
is perfectly healthy.
There's no sign of
any inter-species abnormalities.
"Our" baby?
A figure of speech.
I am, in part,
responsible
for bringing her
into the world.
You may hold her now.
Hello, there.
Congratulations, Samantha.
She's adorable.
Have you thought
of a name?
Not yet.
I really thought
it would be a boy.
Let me know
as soon as you decide.
I've been making
a blanket for her.
All that's missing
is an initial.
Get some rest.
How's our other
patient doing?
She's still
unconscious.
I ran
a microcellular scan.
We're almost identical
in every way.
Almost?
There's a slight
phase shift
in their DNA.
Do you have
any theory
about where
she came from?
Not yet, but I intend
to find out.
Can you wake her?
I believe so.
Good...
because I think
she's going to have
an interesting
story to tell.
I was running
through the corridor
with my medkit...
Deck 15...
And then, suddenly,
I felt dizzy,
and my vision
started to blur.
After that,
I don't remember anything,
until you woke me up
just now.
You were found
unconscious down on Deck 15
holding a medkit.
We also found this
lying next to you.
It's a piece
of damaged conduit.
Our analysis shows
it's from Voyager.
Deck 15,
Section 29-Alpha,
Bulkhead 052.
But there's no damage
to Deck 15
or anywhere else
on this ship.
There was massive damage
to Deck 15.
The evidence
would seem to suggest
that you've come
from a different ship,
a different Voyager.
We did find
a spatial rift on Deck 15.
It's possible that
it somehow connects us
to this other Voyager.
If you're right,
where is the other ship?
A parallel universe?
Another dimension?
Another point in time?
I'm not sure.
Almost everything about
the Voyager Kes described
is identical to ours.
We've had similar experiences,
similar personal histories.
We both entered a plasma cloud
to avoid the Vidiians.
Both of our engines stalled
as we left the cloud,
which caused both of our
antimatter supplies to drain,
and then we both decided
to keep our engines running
by emitting proton bursts.
But after that,
our experiences
diverged.
We started emitting
the proton bursts.
They didn't.
Our ship was being damaged
by proton bursts.
We couldn't figure out
where they were coming from.
That's more
than a coincidence.
Janeway to Engineering.
B'Elanna,
I want you to stop
the proton bursts
immediately.
But if we stop now,
the power levels will...
I'll explain later,
Lieutenant.
Understood.
I don't know how,
but there's
another Voyager out there,
and I intend to find it.
( gentle
dramatic theme playing )
We analyzed the sensor logs
from our trip
through the plasma cloud.
We couldn't find
anything unusual,
until we ran
a quantum-level analysis.
Remember that subspace
turbulence we hit
just before
we left the cloud?
JANEWAY: Yes.
Well, watch what happens.
KIM:
At first, we thought it was
a sensor aberration,
but they were in perfect
calibration at the time.
B'ELANNA: So I ran
a multispectral analysis
on the subspace
turbulence.
It was more
than just turbulence.
It was some kind
of divergence field.
And the moment
we passed through it,
all of our sensor
readings doubled.
Mass, energy output,
bio-signatures-- everything.
Every particle
of matter on the ship
seems to have been
duplicated in that instant.
So where's
the other ship?
As strange
as it sounds, Captain,
according
to these readings,
another Voyager is
right here, right now,
occupying the same point
in space/time that we are.
Quantum theorists
at Kent State University
ran an experiment in which
a single particle of matter
was duplicated using the
divergence of subspace fields--
a spatial scission.
If the same forces were at work
inside the plasma cloud,
they may have duplicated
every particle
of matter on Voyager.
Matter--
but not antimatter.
Captain?
In that Kent
State experiment,
they were able
to duplicate normal matter,
but when they tried to duplicate
antimatter particles,
the experiment failed.
So the antimatter
on the ships
wasn't duplicated.
Both engines have been
trying to draw power
from a single source
of antimatter.
Like Siamese twins
linked at the chest
with only one heart.
So what do we do?
I don't know.
But whatever it is,
we're going to have
to coordinate it
with the other ship.
Start working on a way
to communicate with them.
Right.
The only link we know of
is on Deck 15--
the spatial rift.
We're going to need a way
to send Kes back through safely.
We could rig a portable
phase discriminator.
It might protect her
from the spatial transition.
Get on it.
When can I start
breast feeding?
Right away.
However, I should
forewarn you
that her incisors will erupt
within three to four weeks.
Since your skin lacks
the scales of a Ktarian,
we'll have
to discuss alternatives.
When can I
take her home?
In 24 hours. I want
to observe the infant
to make sure
there's no more damage
to her cell membranes.
You're welcome
to stay the night
so you may be with her.
I'd like that.
( baby crying )
Hey. What's
the matter?
ZIMMERMAN: Congratulations,
Ensign, it's a girl.
I've stabilized
my imaging array
but it could go out
at any time.
KES: Doctor, her cell membranes
are losing cohesion.
ZIMMERMAN: Try remodulating
the osmotic pressure.
KES: No effect.
Again.
Nothing.
WILDMAN: My baby, she's going
to die, isn't she?
ZIMMERMAN:
I'm sorry, Ensign.
( monitor flatlining )
She's going to die,
isn't she?
( baby crying )
ZIMMERMAN ( faintly ):
Kes...
Kes?
( gasps )
Are you all right?
Yes.
It's just...
the baby's crying.
It was like
a bad memory.
What do you mean?
On my Voyager,
during the delivery,
there were complications.
We performed
a fetal transport.
The same thing
happened here.
The transport
was successful.
On my ship, the medical
systems were heavily damaged.
The osmotic pressure
therapy didn't work.
The baby died.
I'm sorry to hear that,
but try to understand,
it wasn't your fault.
The situation was
out of your control.
Doctor, I've got
to get back to my ship.
They need my help.
The captain's
working on it, Kes.
In the meantime,
try to get some rest.
Besides, I'm sure your Voyager
is also equipped
with a proficient
emergency medical hologram.
It's a little harder
to establish
a com link
than I thought, Captain.
The molecular signature
of the second Voyager
is slightly out of phase
with our own.
I can't get visual,
audio-- nothing.
Have you tried remodulating
the com-frequency carrier?
Five times on 47
different frequencies.
There has to be a way.
If they were recalibrating
their carrier wave
at the same time--
so we could match
phase variants--
would that allow us
to connect?
I think so, but in order
to get them to do that
we'd have to communicate
with them first.
It's the chicken
and the egg.
Maybe we need something
a little more primitive.
Is there a signal we could
emit on all subspace bands
just to get their attention?
A rotating band pulse
might do it,
but it wouldn't
be much more
than a shrill whistle.
That might be enough,
give it a try.
All right, Captain.
All of the ship's
command functions
have been rerouted
to Main Engineering.
JANEWAY: Welcome
to the new Bridge.
Now, let's see about...
( shrill tone )
What's that?
TORRES: I don't know.
It's some kind of com-emissions
coming through
all subspace bands.
Coming from where?
Good question.
I can't tell,
but it's got
a Federation signature.
Try recalibrating our frequency
carrier to match it.
( shrill tone )
That's it.
They recalibrated
and locked onto
our phase variant.
What kind of communication
can we establish?
Not much at this point.
We can use
the emergency encryption code
for a short message.
Not more
than five seconds.
That should be enough.
JANEWAY 1:
That's the emergency code.
Run it through an
alpha-numeric sequencer.
TORRES:
I think someone's telling us
to lock onto a frequency
of 12 gigahertz.
Do it.
I'll try to clear it up.
Captain,
this isn't an illusion.
What you're seeing is real,
but it's going to take
some explaining.
There are two Voyagers
and two crews?
That's what I was told.
Could this possibly be
some kind
of subterfuge, Captain?
An alien deception?
That woman,
whoever she is,
had very specific
knowledge
of what happened here--
the damage from
the proton bursts,
Wildman's baby,
Kes disappearing.
She even knew that when
I was 12 years old,
I walked home
in a thunderstorm
over seven kilometers
because I lost
a tennis match.
And her explanation
of how the ships
were duplicated--
certainly plausible.
If it is true,
what do we do about it?
My... counterpart
has suggested we try
to merge the two ships.
Recreate the subspace
divergence field
we passed through
and then depolarize it.
Both ships would have
to send out
a massive resonance pulse
from their deflector dishes
at exactly the same time.
They may be able
to do that,
but we barely
have enough power
for life support.
How can we get enough to send
an energy pulse of that size?
We could evacuate
all the crew to this deck
and cut off life support
everywhere else.
Then we could divert
all power to the deflector dish.
B'Elanna, reestablish
the com link
with the other ship.
This is Janeway.
What have you decided?
Captain, we think we can
channel enough energy
to our deflector dish
to try the merging process.
Good.
When can we start?
We'll need
at least 15 minutes
to make
our preparations.
We'll be ready.
And Captain...
we'll only have enough
power to try this once.
I understand.
Chakotay, Tuvok--
begin the evacuation process.
Aye, Captain.
I'll tell the doctor know
he'll have to rely
on his backup
power supply.
( beeping )
( sighs )
We're ready, Captain.
We're standing by,
Captain.
I think you should
take the lead
in this operation
since you may have
to make allowances
for your weakened
power systems.
Acknowledged.
Lieutenant Torres,
and Lieutenant Torres.
Charge the
deflector dishes.
Deflector dish charging.
Capacitance levels
are rising.
Sixty percent.
Eighty-five percent.
Ninety-eight percent...
We're ready to create
the subspace divergence field.
Initiating.
Power flow nominal,
Captain.
Synchronize
computer event timing.
Ready to release
depolarization pulse
on my mark.
Now.
The pulses have been
emitted, Captain.
The fields are starting
to depolarize.
But we aren't merging.
In fact, we're going
further out of phase!
Increase power
to the deflector dish.
I can't! Too much
plasma backflow.
If we keep this up,
we're going to lose
our antimatter connection.
We'll both be destroyed.
Abort!
Aborting resonance pulse.
What went wrong?
I'm not sure.
I think the plasma flow
became too turbulent.
The divergence fields
were so chaotic
we couldn't complete
the merging.
We've lost
the com link as well.
( gasps )
Captain,
the antimatter leak?
It's becoming
a hemorrhage.
If we don't start
the proton bursts,
we'll be completely
drained in 30 minutes.
The lives of both crews
are at stake here.
I can't make
unilateral decisions
that might affect
that other ship.
Janeway to Kim.
Is the spatial rift
still stable?
I think so, Captain,
and I've rigged
a phase discriminator.
Kes should be able
to go back safely.
Rig another one,
Ensign.
I'm going with her.
This should protect you
from the spatial
transition.
Keep trying to reestablish
a com-link between the ships.
I will. But remember,
we have fewer than 30 minutes
of antimatter left.
Whatever you do over
there, do it fast.
Understood.
Are you ready?
Yes.
It's gotten worse here.
Command Control
is in Main Engineering.
Let's go.
I don't know how else to stop
the antimatter drain,
except with proton bursts.
We can't do that.
We'd damage the other ship
just like this one.
Think, people.
We need options.
I agree, Captain.
And I think we need to talk.
By my estimates,
our antimatter supply
will run out in less than
half an hour.
The attempt
to merge our ships
is throwing us further
out of phase.
The quantum cohesion
on both Voyagers
is breaking down.
Just like the original
Kent State experiment.
The duplicate atoms couldn't
occupy the same point
in space/time
for very long before...
Mutual
annihilation.
What are our options?
Let's try
a different tack.
Instead of trying
to merge the two ships,
let's try
to separate them.
Maybe we could divide
the antimatter between us.
I'm afraid not.
We've been studying
that theory.
B'Elanna tells me that
any attempt to disrupt
the antimatter supply
would destroy us all.
What about evacuating
your crew to my ship?
It might get crowded,
but we could manage.
We've been studying
that theory,
and my B'Elanna
tells me that
sending any more than five
to ten people through the rift
would radically alter
the atomic balance
of the two Voyagers.
We'd both be destroyed.
Captain, I think you should
return to your ship
and run a metallurgical
analysis.
Find out the precise phase
modulation of your hull.
I'll do the same here.
Maybe we can find a way
to realign
the phase displacement.
You're going
to self-destruct your ship.
What makes you say that?
Because that's what I would do
if your Voyager were intact
and my Voyager
were crippled.
My crew wounded or dead.
I'd sacrifice my ship
so that yours could survive.
Then I'm glad we agree.
Go back to your ship.
I didn't say I agree.
I said I understand.
I'm not willing to let you
make that sacrifice yet.
We haven't explored
all the options.
Yes, we have,
and we both know it.
This is my ship
and my decision.
Captain,
I'm not going to let--
I've made my decision.
Please don't make me
call security
and have you escorted
off my ship because...
( quiet )
you know I'll do it.
All right,
I'll go back,
but give me 15 minutes
to come up
with another solution.
After that,
it's your decision.
15 minutes.
Good luck.
To both of us.
Okay, I've managed
to reestablish a com-link
with the other Voyager.
Hail them.
Captain,
I've got an idea.
Actually, it was yours.
It might be possible
to realign
the phase displacement
between us.
We don't have time
to try it.
My plan is the one
that's going to work.
It's time that
we both accept that.
( alarm wailing )
We've got
a perimeter alert.
A vessel
is approaching
bearing 005 mark 318.
They've just
dropped out of warp.
Can you identify them?
They're
Vidiian, sir.
Red Alert.
Shields.
Still off-line.
Captain, we're picking up
a Vidiian ship heading this way.
Can you see them too?
Yes.
Do you have any weapons?
Stand by.
Tuvok?
Negative, Captain.
We had to reroute power
to compensate
for the antimatter loss.
It would take several hours
to bring weapons
back on-line.
VIDIIAN COMMANDER:
What is it?
Their ship seems
to be trapped
in some sort of
spatial flux.
Have they detected us?
Yes, but they can't
raise their shields.
And it appears that whatever is
happening to them has disrupted
their weapons systems.
Load a hyper-thermic charge.
Fire.
Captain, they have fired
an energy weapon.
All hands, brace for impact.
Damage Control teams
stand by.
( all grunting )
What happened?
They couldn't have missed.
Maybe they hit
the other Voyager.
Hail them.
I've lost the com-link again.
Try to get it back.
We have destroyed
their weapons array.
Maneuver us to within
grappling range.
They are cutting an access route
through the hull on Deck 5.
( dramatic theme playing )
( both grunt )
( sensor beeping )
Vulcan, male.
Phaser blast damaged
the right kidney,
but the other organs
are healthy.
Begin with them.
( grunts )
( sensor beeping )
I've erected an emergency
force field around Sick Bay--
that should hold them off
for a while.
I won't let them
take my baby.
It's going to be
all right, Ensign.
Give her to me
and I'll hide her
inside an access port.
If they do break in,
it's unlikely
they'll look for
anyone there.
( baby crying )
Trust me, Ensign.
I won't let anyone
touch our baby.
Mama will see you soon.
Lieutenant, give me a hand.
Move this.
We're going to have
to cut away
the internal circuitry
to make room...
( phaser blast )
Vidiians.
They're using some kind
of disrupter
to break down the force field.
The force field's down.
JANEWAY:
Commander...
They've got everything
below Deck 5,
and I don't know
how much longer
we can keep them away
from the Bridge.
Mr. Kim, how many Vidiians
are there on this ship?
347 and more
are boarding.
We're outnumbered
two to one.
I've got an incoming
subspace signal.
It's from
the other Voyager.
They must have reestablished
the com-link.
Onscreen.
Captain, this com-link
might not last much longer.
What's happening
over there?
We've been boarded.
The Vidiians are on the verge
of taking over our ship.
Are they on yours?
No. We don't think
they can detect our ship.
Captain, we can have
a security detachment
cross the spatial rift
and board your ship
within five minutes.
No. If we do that,
the Vidiians might become aware
of your Voyager.
That would put
both ships at risk.
We can't just stand by
and let you all be killed.
I'm not about
to let that happen.
I'll destroy this ship.
I don't suppose there's any way
I can change your mind.
I know how stubborn
you can be.
True.
But there is something else
I can do for you.
I'm going to send Harry Kim
through the rift
with Ensign
Wildman's baby.
Somehow
it seems only fair.
We'll be waiting
for them.
Just make me
a promise, Kathryn.
Get your crew home.
I will.
Harry, you've
got five minutes.
Get the baby.
But Captain--
Move it, Ensign!
That's an order!
Computer, initiate
the self-destruct sequence.
Authorization
Janeway Pi 1-1-0.
Set at five minutes
and mute voice warnings.
Enable.
COMPUTER: Warning. Self-destruct
sequence has been initiated.
Warp core overload
in four minutes, 55 seconds.
There will be
no further audio warnings.
( dramatic theme playing )
Ocampa, female.
The organs are healthy.
She has an extremely high rate
of tissue regeneration.
Extract her pelvic ridge.
We'll analyze
the bone marrow
for phage resistance.
VIDIIAN 1:
The others are human.
My scans indicate
their pancreatic tissues
are well-suited
for transplant.
VIDIIAN 2: Begin the
extraction procedure.
( gasps )
Shh.
( whimpers )
This one--
a female human.
She's recently
given birth.
Are you certain?
Yes. Her hemo-uterine
levels are far above normal.
Where's the infant?
Set your bio-pro
to maximum. Find it.
( whimpering )
Shh... Shh, shh.
( Vidiian voices speaking
indistinctly nearby )
( both Vidiians
speaking indistinctly )
( grunts )
No!
Ensign Kim,
is that you?
Doc!
Am I glad
to see you.
Have we retaken the ship?
No. Actually, the captain's put
the ship on self-destruct.
She ordered me
to take the baby
and go
to the other Voyager.
Well, I guess you'd
better hurry then.
Goodbye, Doc.
Ensign, tell
my counterpart
that I've corrected
all signs of hemocythemia.
He'll know what
that means.
Will do.
Hello.
I'm Captain
Kathryn Janeway.
Welcome to the Bridge.
Commander!
( beeping )
( B'Elanna sighs )
It's about time.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Ensign Kim has made it
through the rift.
With the infant.
Acknowledged.
Captain,
the Vidiian ship
has been destroyed.
So has the other Voyager.
( building dramatic score )
JANEWAY: Captain's log,
Stardate 49548.7.
There are no signs
of any pursuing Vidiian vessels
and we have resumed
a course toward home.
Repair efforts
are underway.
Lieutenant
Torres estimates
we'll be able
to return to the Bridge
within three days.
Good. I'm not sure
how much longer
B'Elanna can tolerate
my standing over
her shoulder in Engineering.
Hm...
Tuvok, is there something
on your mind?
I am curious, Captain.
Before the
Vidiians attacked,
when you were
in disagreement
with the other captain...
Would I have given
the order
to self-destruct our ship?
I've gone over that moment
a thousand times in my mind.
The truth is, yes,
I would've given the order.
But I will admit,
there was a part of me
that could see
her point of view.
One could say that
you are both the doubter
and the doubted.
I do not envy
the paradox of logic
you were faced with
in that situation.
Neither did I.
And neither did she.
( cooing )
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
But you should also
thank the doctor.
It was his counterpart
who saved her
from the Vidiians.
I'm not surprised.
I am programmed to be heroic
when the need arises.
By the way, Ensign,
this other doctor,
did he have a name?
I really didn't
have time to ask.
Am I allowed
to go back
to my temporary
Bridge now, Doctor?
By all means.
( baby cooing )
It's good to have
you back, Ensign.
Thank you.
I think.
Something wrong?
I'm not sure.
I mean, this isn't
really my ship.
And you're not really
my captain,
and yet you are,
and there's no difference,
but I know
there's a difference.
Or is there?
It's all
a little weird.
Mr. Kim, we're
Starfleet officers.
Weird is part
of the job.
( dramatic theme playing )
( dramatic
theme music playing )