Tuvok to Voyager.
Voyager,
do you read?
( groaning )
You must lie still.
I-I-I can't feel my legs.
Several of your vertebrae
have been fractured.
Isn't there anything you can do?
I'm afraid the shuttle's
medical supplies are inadequate.
We must wait
for Voyager to find us.
( gasping )
It's getting worse.
My whole body feels numb.
I want you to slow
your breathing
and relax
your muscles.
Try not to move.
A-All this time I thought...
I thought I was so lucky--
No family back home...
nobody to miss.
Now it seems kind of sad not,
not to leave anybody behind.
I believe
Ensign Macormak
would miss you a great deal.
You think so?
I was never really sure
how sh... sh...
( tricorder beeping )
( tricorder emits steady tone)
( foliage rustles )
It's all right.
Don't be frightened.
I won't hurt you.
Let me go!
Will you run if I do?
No.
( sighs )
My name is Tuvok.
Who are you?
Tressa.
You don't look like us.
I am not a member of your race.
I am Vulcan.
I thought this moon
was uninhabited.
Do you live here?
We came here on a ship,
but it crashed, like yours.
Where are your parents?
Dead.
Is he dead too?
Yes.
What were you doing to him?
I put a stasis field
around his body to protect it
until I can take it back
to my ship.
Why?
Some cultures,
like Mr. Bennet's,
consider an appropriate burial
to be a sign of respect.
Tressa,
is there anyone else
here with you?
It's all right.
There is no one
looking after you?
Everyone else died
in the crash.
We're alone.
There is no reason to be afraid.
I will take care of you now and
see that you get home safely.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I've sent out scouting parties
to analyze the mineral deposits
in the moons around Drayan II.
Meanwhile,
I've arranged a meeting
with the planet's leader.
According to Neelix,
nobody's had direct contact
with the Drayans
for decades.
All he's heard are rumors.
Do any of those rumors
describe them as hostile?
No. Just very private.
That's something.
Deck 4.
My diplomacy professor
used to say
the opening 20 minutes
of a first-contact situation
are the most crucial.
I'd feel better
about this particular 20 minutes
if we had some idea
what to expect.
Sometimes, you have
to go in blind.
That's the exciting part.
When I was a
Science Officer,
I always envied
the Captain's privilege
of making first contact
with new races.
I envied it so much,
I almost got myself shipped
back to the Academy
for remedial training.
On my first assignment,
we were sent to make contact
with the Tarkannans.
I studied all the information
we had about them
and pestered the Captain
into letting me be part
of the diplomatic team.
When we came face-to-face
with the Tarkannan delegation,
I very proudly made the
traditional gesture for "hello,"
not realizing that males
and females of their race
use different styles
of movement, and I was
actually propositioning
the ambassador.
Energize.
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway.
I'd like to welcome
you aboard
the Federation
Starship Voyager.
First Prelate Alcia.
May this day find
you at peace
and leave you with hope.
That's a traditional
blessing
from our ancient scrolls.
Om-nah-hoo-pez-nyeetz.
That's from the spirits
of my people.
It means, "peace in your heart,
fortune in your steps."
It's very gracious of you
to agree to meet with us.
We don't often engage in
dialogue with alien races,
but your story of crossing
the galaxy intrigued me.
I'd be glad to tell you all
about our journey and my crew.
Perhaps you'd like to see
more of our ship as well.
Thank you.
JANEWAY:
Our warp core
is designed to operate
for up to three years
before refueling.
CHAKOTAY:
The reaction chamber is
equipped with a compositor,
which allows us to
recrystallize the dilithium.
In our situation,
we can never be sure
when we'll be able
to find a new supply.
I'm sorry my Chief Engineer
isn't here to meet you.
She's leading one
of the away teams
surveying the moons
around Drayan.
I find it interesting
that you chose this
to show me first.
Do your people consider
advanced technology
to be their
highest achievement?
Not as an end in itself.
The purpose of all this
is to help us gain knowledge
about the universe
and the people in it.
Our ancestors were
brilliant scientists
and engineers.
They were continually
developing
better, smarter, more
efficient machines,
until the technology
became more important
than the people.
I believe that society
would have self-destructed
if it weren't for
the Reformation.
My great-grandfather
helped to return us
to ourselves, and
since that time,
we've remained isolated
to avoid the influence
of those who might lead us
back down the wrong path.
Some human cultures
have done the same.
Will your friend be
all right in there?
Yes, I have secured his body
within the stasis field.
You are all very fortunate
to have escaped the crash
with only a few bruises.
The attendants protected us.
Attendants?
The people on our ship.
They got us to the escape pod
before they crashed.
Can we go now?
I want to go.
Are we going to fly
in your ship?
He said it was a shuttle,
not a ship.
We cannot leave yet.
My shuttle
is in need of repairs.
Can't you fix it?
I believe so.
However, I am more concerned
with getting through
the electrodynamic turbulence
in the ionosphere.
What's electro turbulence?
A thermal inversion gradient
is causing unusually strong
and unpredictable currents
in the upper levels
of the atmosphere.
Those currents caused
my shuttle to crash,
and I assume, yours as well.
I must find a way to safely
navigate through the turbulence
before we can attempt to leave.
Will that take
a long time?
It may.
You must be patient.
I don't want
to stay here anymore.
I don't like it here.
Your displeasure doesn't change
our situation,
nor does it bring us
any closer to a solution.
You don't have to be
so mean about it.
It isn't my intention
to be mean.
I only wish to provide you
with a realistic assessment.
Vulcan parents never shield
their children from the truth.
Doing so would only hinder
their ability to cope
with inevitable difficulties.
I'm hungry.
There is a supply of Starfleet
rations in the shuttle.
What's rations?
Concentrated, vitamin-enriched
nutritional supplements.
I want takka berries.
With cherel sauce.
We have only rations.
( sighs )
Now, I must begin working
on my shuttle.
By my estimate, we have fewer
than four hours
of daylight remaining.
We can't be here
when it's night.
That's when
the morrok comes.
Is that a species of animal?
The morrok is what
takes you when you die.
It lives here...
in the cave.
I'm not detecting any life-forms
other than ourselves.
It's here.
It'll come.
Have any of you ever
seen this creature?
You can only see it
when it comes for you.
Then it's too late.
I believe your anxiety
about our situation
is causing you
to imagine the presence...
It took
the others!
Jarren and Fayla--
The other children on the ship.
The morrok took them
while we were sleeping...
and tonight, it will take us.
The Federation consists
of over 150 different worlds
who have agreed to share
their knowledge and resources
in peaceful
cooperation.
Ah, visitors.
Welcome to Sick Bay.
I'm the Chief Medical Officer.
This is First Prelate
Alcia of Drayan II.
It's an honor
to meet you.
We don't often receive
such distinguished guests here,
unless there's been
some sort of accident.
I'm... sure nothing unfortunate
will happen to you
on your visit here, but if
it did, you can rest assured
you will find yourself
in very capable hands.
We are fully
equipped to provide
a wide variety
of treatments here,
from removing a splinter
to resequencing the base pairs
in a strand of DNA.
And our research facilities
are the most advanced
in Starfleet.
Very impressive.
You may be even more
interested to learn
that this man isn't really
a biological life-form.
He's a computer-generated
holographic projection.
My people believe
that physical matter's
only an illusion.
The body is not
the true self,
only a representation.
One of our greatest
philosophers, Plato,
wrote that what
we see around us
are only poor shadows
of ideal objects,
which exist on
a higher plane.
That is similar
to our teachings.
Our connection to what you call
a higher plane
is more important
than our attachment
to this brief existence,
however real it may seem.
KIM:
Bridge to Captain.
There's an incoming message
for the First Prelate.
Perhaps you'd like
to use my office.
Uh, yes.
Thank you, Doctor...?
I'm afraid
it's just Doctor.
Patch it through
on a secure channel
to the Doctor's office, Mr. Kim.
Acknowledged.
You did very well.
I think she was impressed.
Kes has been coaching me
on my diplomatic skills.
It shows.
Our next step will be
to open negotiations--
Find out what they
might be interested
in getting from us
in exchange for
the polyferranide.
I've been called away
on an emergency.
Is there anything
we can do to help?
No. Thank you. It would be
better if you and your crew
continued on your journey.
It's been
an interesting visit.
We'd been hoping to
learn more about you.
It's been our custom
for generations
to avoid close contact
with outsiders.
I choose to honor
that tradition.
Goodbye, Captain.
I hope you find your way home.
Was it something I said?
We could assure her
we have no intention
of interfering with their
culture or traditions.
No. She made
her wishes clear.
If we're not welcome, we'll go.
Recall the scouting parties.
We'll have to find our
polyferranide somewhere else.
Where did you last see
the missing children?
By the big tree,
when we went
to sleep last night.
Were either
of them injured?
Jarren hurt his hand.
But both were able
to walk?
Uh-huh.
Did any of you hear them
get up during the night?
You think they wandered
off and got lost,
but they didn't.
The morrok took them.
They're gone.
The other children
aren't within scanning range
of this tricorder.
That is the only thing we know
for certain at this time.
You don't understand.
We have to get away from here.
Please, can we go?
I'm scared.
Please, Tuvok?
Children, you are allowing
your fears to guide you.
You must learn
to exercise control
over your own imagination.
But the morrok!
Yes.
The existence of such a creature
is one possibility.
However, your emotional
reactions are preventing you
from accurately judging
how unlikely that is to be true.
I can't help it.
I'm scared.
I believe you can help it.
Vulcan children learn to detach
themselves from their emotions
at an early age.
How?
First, you must focus
on the object of your fear.
Picture the morrok
clearly in your minds.
That image is accompanied
by an emotional response.
Describe for me
what that feeling is like.
It makes my stomach
all tight.
I feel like I want to run,
but my legs won't work.
Now, if you could see this
emotion in physical form,
what would it look like?
It's like this big black cloud
with lots of thunder
and lightning all around us.
Then imagine a strong wind
is pushing that cloud away.
Watch as your fear
grows more distant.
It is no longer
a part of you.
Once you begin
to detach yourselves
from your emotional responses,
you come closer
to controlling them.
Eventually, they will be
eliminated altogether.
Do you live your whole life
without feeling anything?
More accurately, we strive
to control our feelings.
You don't get scared... ever?
No.
Even when your shuttle crashed?
That is correct.
But what if there was
this big hairy tardeth
coming after you...
The circumstances
are irrelevant.
A Vulcan approaches
every situation logically.
Now, I must begin work
on my shuttle.
We will resume the search
for the other children
once the sensors
are operational.
I expect each of you
to sit quietly
and not touch
any of the equipment.
We promise.
( laughing and squealing )
Elani, please,
put that down.
Let me have it!
No! I found it!
( loud whirring )
Be careful with that!
You...
will stay here.
And you...
Where do I get to sit?
But I want to sit next to you.
Tuvok?
Yes?
Why do your ears
look like that?
All Vulcans have
similarly shaped ears.
Why?
It is a result
of many millennia
of evolution.
Do they make you hear better?
No.
Where do Vulcans live?
Is it far away?
My home world is on the
other side of the galaxy.
Elani. Elani!
I asked you not
to play with that.
Sorry.
What are you doing?
It helps prepare you to
attain a meditative state.
Now close your eyes
and imagine all the
energy in your body
is flowing to the point
where your fingertips meet.
Nothing else you hear
or feel is important.
Let the outside
world fade away.
You exist only
inside your mind.
Tuvok?
Yes?
Do you have any children?
Be quiet.
We are trying to attain
a meditative state.
But I want to know.
I have four children.
Now, you must concentrate.
What are they like?
Well-behaved.
They had already mastered
several states of
heightened awareness
by the time they
were your age.
If Vulcans
don't feel anything,
does that mean
you don't love them?
My attachment to my children
cannot be described
as an emotion.
They are part
of my identity.
And I am...
incomplete without them.
I bet they miss you, too.
COWIN:
Tuvok?
Yes?
I have to scratch my nose.
You may.
TRESSA:
Tuvok!
Yes!
I hear something.
Is it a ship?
I believe so.
Can you see
who it is?
The sensors are
only partially functional.
I'm attempting
to identify the ship
by its shield harmonics.
Is somebody coming
to save us?
It is not a shuttle
from Voyager.
The pattern of the harmonics
matches that of the ships
we scanned in orbit
around Drayan.
It seems your people
have come looking for you.
We have to
hide, Tuvok.
You can't let them
find us here.
I don't understand.
I thought you wanted to go home.
They won't take us home.
They're the ones who
made us come here.
For what purpose?
They sent us here to die.
We have to go.
If they find us,
we'll all die.
Please, Tuvok.
Why would your own people
want to harm you?
Please.
They're coming.
Help us.
( instruments whirring )
( indistinct conversation )
DRAYAN:
Any indication
where they've gone?
DRAYAN 2:
No.
DRAYAN:
Spread out
and scan the area.
Two of them are
coming this way.
What are you doing?
This will hide us
from their scanners.
( instrument whirring )
DRAYAN:
I'm not picking up
any life-forms this way.
Why do you believe
they've come to kill you?
We're supposed
to die here.
That's what this place is for.
They bring children here
for the final ritual.
Then the morrok
takes them away.
No one ever comes back.
TUVOK:
It is illogical
for a society to kill
its own children.
The scrolls
say we should be happy--
That when we die, the energy
inside us is set free.
Is it true?
Is that what
really happens?
Vulcans believe that
a person's katra--
What some might
call a soul--
Continues to exist
after the body dies.
Do you believe that?
When I was younger,
I accepted it
without question.
In recent years, I have
experienced doubts.
I do believe there is
more within each of us
than science
has yet explained.
I know
we should have more faith.
It's wrong
to be afraid of death.
There is nothing wrong
in choosing to live.
Will you help us?
Until I can gain
a better understanding
of your situation,
I believe
it would be best
to get you safely
back to Voyager.
Torres and Neelix
just got back,
but there's still no word
from Tuvok and Bennet.
I'm not picking up
their shuttle on sensors.
KIM:
There's heavy solar
flare activity.
It's causing
electrodynamic disturbance
throughout the system.
We found a vein
of pure polyferranide
three kilometers long.
It's a real shame we're leaving.
When was your last contact
with the other team?
Several hours ago.
Is there a problem?
We can't reach them.
When we spoke to them,
they were going to check out
the outermost moons.
Can you find
the shuttle's ion signature?
I'm reading one
on heading 151 mark 8.
That's where Neelix and I went.
And another one
on a divergent course,
20 degrees to starboard.
Set a course, Mr. Paris.
Our scans of the moon
are inconclusive.
We can't see anything through
the turbulence
in the atmosphere.
The Drayan ship still hasn't
responded to our hails.
Are you sure our signal's
getting through?
They're receiving it.
They're just
not answering.
Continue hails.
This desecration
dishonors us both, Captain.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand...
This moon is our crysata...
sacred ground.
Your presence
is forbidden here.
We've only come here
to look for one of our shuttles.
It's missing.
We found your shuttle
on the surface.
The pilot is dead.
There were two men on board.
Did you find both of them?
No, only one.
If there's someone else
on this moon,
you must transport him back
to your ship immediately.
That's what we intend to do.
This kind of disturbance
is exactly why we avoid contact
with outsiders.
I was wrong to respond
to your communication.
I should have known better
than to indulge my curiosity.
There's no one at fault here.
The shuttle crash
was an accident.
One I expect you to correct
as soon as possible.
What's the status
of the transporters?
The targeting scanners
still can't lock
on to anything
on the surface.
It would be easier
if we sent down another shuttle.
No, that would only
make things worse.
( sighs ):
I'll keep working on it.
( instrument whirring )
I don't see how you
could be thirsty again
after four drinks
of water.
Aren't you going
to sleep?
I can go several days
without rest if necessary.
You cannot.
It's warmer by the fire.
Go back and
try to sleep.
Do not worry.
I have run several
thorough scans of the area.
There are no other
life-forms present--
Inside the cave
or anywhere within
5 kilometers.
Maybe the morrok doesn't
show up on the scans.
I am also keeping watch
on all of you from here.
If there is any
indication of trouble,
I'll come immediately.
Okay.
We can't sleep.
( sighs )
Apparently not.
It's so dark.
I think the
fire's going out.
Maybe you should look.
I added more wood less
than a half an hour ago.
However,
it might be wise
to check it again.
I always have
my hair brushed
before I go to sleep.
I like to hear a story.
Tell us one about the
fire beast of Sullus.
I never understood
the practice in some cultures
of describing
ferocious creatures
in an attempt
to lull children to sleep.
Don't Vulcans tell
bedtime stories?
If my children
had difficulty sleeping,
I would play music for them.
I like music.
Unfortunately,
I don't have my lute.
What's that?
It is a five-stringed
instrument
tuned on a
diatonic scale.
It can be
very soothing.
My youngest son was
particularly fond of it.
He always used to ask me
to play "Falor's Journey."
It is a tale
of enlightenment
consisting
of 348 verses.
It may not be necessary to
include the complete narrative.
Falor was a prosperous merchant
who went on a journey
to gain greater awareness.
"Through storms,
he crossed the Voroth Sea
"to reach the clouded
shores of Raal,
where old T'Para
offered truth."
♪ He traveled through
The windswept hills ♪
♪ And crossed
The barren Fire Plains ♪
♪ To find the silent monks
Of Kir ♪
♪ Still unfulfilled ♪
♪ He journeyed home ♪
♪ Told stories
Of the lessons learned ♪
♪ And gained true wisdom
By the giving... ♪
Tuvok! Tuvok!
They're gone.
Captain, you might want
to see this.
Have you found the shuttle?
Actually,
we've found two.
Both crashed
on the surface.
The sensor resolution
is still quite low.
This looks like
our shuttle.
I'd guess the other
one is Drayan.
We've also had
some indications
of life signs
on the surface.
A while ago, there seemed
to be four of them.
Now we can only
distinguish two.
I've been working
on the transporters.
It just isn't possible
to get a pattern lock
through all
the turbulence.
Then we've got to start
considering other options.
I want a full analysis
of the atmospheric conditions
and your best suggestion of how
to get a shuttle to the surface.
Then let's hope
we won't need to try it.
There were no
other life forms
and no unusual energy readings
within sensor range all night.
It was the morrok.
Why don't you believe me?
( sighing ):
Very well.
I'll investigate.
I'd like you
to wait here
while I look
inside the cave.
But if you go in there,
you won't come out.
I will take
every possible precaution.
I believe you can be responsible
with this.
Aim like this
and press here
to fire.
I'll seal the shuttle's
door while I'm gone.
No, Tuvok. Don't leave me
all by myself. Please!
If there is anything
in the cave,
it may help us determine
what has been happening here.
It is very important to gather
as much information as possible.
I'm scared.
We often fear
what we do not understand.
Our best defense is knowledge.
You must trust
me, Tressa.
I'll return shortly.
Promise?
I will not abandon you.
( console beeping )
( door opens )
What did you see in there?
I realize it
may frighten you,
but you must hear
the truth.
Suffice it to say,
I did not find
the other children,
nor do I have
any explanation
of what happened to them.
I'm going to be next,
aren't I?
There's nothing
we can do about it.
The disappearances have
occurred only at night.
We will attempt to leave
here before the sun sets.
I'll really be quiet this time.
I won't touch anything.
That would make it
difficult for you
to assist me with repairs.
The Drayans have just
sent another shuttle
down to the moon, Captain.
There must be at least 20
people on the surface.
I can't tell if
the two life-forms
we detected before
are still there.
How many search parties
could it take
to find two crash victims?
Captain, there's a break
in the turbulence.
I'm picking up
a com signal.
Tuvok to Voyager.
Voyager, do you read?
We read you, Tuvok.
Are you all right?
Yes, Captain,
but Ensign Bennet is dead.
We know. We've been trying
to get you off the surface,
but we're having some trouble
with the Drayans.
They insist on sending
their own search parties.
Yes, I have been avoiding them.
Why?
I have a young girl with me
who claims
they have come to kill her.
I was reluctant
to believe it at first,
but several other children
have disappeared.
( static intensifies )
There's nothing
I can do, Captain.
The signal's
breaking up.
Tuvok, what happened
to the other children?
They have disappeared.
Something on this moon
is responsible.
We must leave here.
I'm attempting to repair...
Scan Tuvok's shuttle for damage.
Will he be able to get himself
out of there?
There's no structural damage.
Some power fluctuations.
He should be able to take off.
What if they can't?
Hail the Drayan ship.
ALCIA:
Captain.
First Prelate,
it's come to my attention
that you have a damaged ship
on the surface as well
and there may be survivors.
I'd like to offer our help
in finding them.
Perhaps a joint
rescue operation...
That won't be necessary,
Captain.
You've been intrusive enough.
Our sensor readings indicate
the people on the surface
may be in trouble.
I'm sure you must be
as concerned
for their safety as we are.
There's no reason to fear for
anyone's safety on the crysata.
It's a blessed haven,
sheltered and unspoiled,
which is the very reason
why I can't allow you
to go there
under any circumstances.
Then I regret to inform you
I'll be taking a shuttle
to the surface
without your permission.
That's completely unacceptable.
I believe it's necessary.
If you launch
one of your shuttles,
I will be forced to send
one of ours after you.
First Prelate, it's not my
intention to provoke a conflict.
Well, then leave at once.
I'll be glad to,
as soon as every member
of my crew
is safely back on board
this ship.
Janeway out.
Lieutenant, you're with me.
Mr. Kim, I need
your report.
I've been studying
the energy signature
of the Drayan shuttles.
They're using some kind
of dielectric field
to protect them
from the turbulence.
We could generate
the same kind of field
with our shuttle's
warp coils.
It won't be very stable.
It might be
a rough ride,
but we can make it.
Captain, maybe you shouldn't...
I know the risks, Commander,
but if there's any hope
left for a diplomatic
solution,
I've got to be down there
to see it through.
Let's get through
the preflight quickly.
Thrusters, impulse
engines, warp drive...
All propulsion systems
are nominal.
Shields, phasers, inertial
dampers, com system.
I think we've got
all the basics.
Computer, initiate
cold launch sequence.
Or we could just skip
preflight altogether.
Definitely not recommended,
but sometimes necessary.
I'll remember that.
I'm taking the warp drive
off-line.
Setting up the dielectric field.
It's holding, but we'll
have to keep an eye
on the stabilizer integrity.
Janeway to Bridge.
Depressurize the shuttle bay
and open the space doors.
CHAKOTAY:
Aye, Captain.
Captain, I'm picking up
a Drayan shuttle.
They're on an
intercept course.
Can we outrun them?
The dielectric field
is weakening our
structural integrity.
If we go much faster,
I'm afraid we'll break up.
We're improvising here.
The Drayans aren't.
We're on their home turf.
They have every advantage.
That may be reason enough
for them not to fire on us.
We'll be testing that theory
in a few seconds.
They're about to enter
weapons range, Captain.
Raise shields to maximum
and stand ready
to power the weapons.
Maneuvering thrusters
and impulse engines
are functional.
We're ready to lift off.
What about the electro...?
The currents that
made the ships crash?
I have determined that
a dielectric field
should allow us to
pass through them.
However, you should
still be prepared
for some turbulence.
Initiating prelaunch sequence.
Number three thruster
is failing.
Attempting to stabilize.
Drayan shuttle's
closing fast, Captain.
They'll overtake us
before we can land.
They haven't powered
their weapon systems.
Maybe they're
still willing to talk.
Let's hope the ones on the
surface feel the same way.
We'll be through this ionosphere
in a few more minutes.
Sensors are clearing up.
I'm reading Tuvok's shuttle.
He's trying to lift off,
but it looks
like there's some trouble
with the thrusters.
( console beeps )
And there's
a large Drayan search party
approaching his location.
I see them.
They're coming
all around us.
We've got to go-- Now.
I'm attempting
an emergency procedure.
Please move away
from the console.
You did it!
You saved me.
I regret that may be
a premature conclusion.
The process
of powering the thrusters
has left us with minimal shields
and no functional weapons.
Voyager will be
watching for us.
When we clear the atmosphere,
we can be transported
aboard the ship.
Then what are we going to do?
You may request asylum
with the Federation if you wish.
Then we'll be able
to protect you.
I want to stay with you.
( console beeping )
The Drayan shuttle
is hailing us.
You're holding
one of our children.
I want to speak to her.
She believes
you intend to kill her.
Is that true?
The child is confused.
I only want to help her.
You want me to die.
Tressa, I understand how
confusing this must be for you.
If you return to the surface,
I will answer all questions.
No. I'm not going back there.
I'm staying with Tuvok.
We can resolve this matter
aboard Voyager.
Unacceptable.
If you or any of your people
attempt to take Tressa
back to your ship,
I will use any means necessary
to stop you.
Do what you will.
Very well.
Fire.
( screaming )
We weren't hit.
I believe that was a warning.
I've got phasers locked on
the Drayan shuttle, Captain.
Don't fire.
We might be able
to transport Tuvok from here.
( beeping )
There's still
too much interference.
We should be close enough
to get a com-signal through.
Tuvok, we're on our
way to the surface.
We'll intercept you
in a few moments.
That may be too late, Captain.
I'm losing power rapidly.
I believe another hit
will force me to land.
Go back down to the surface.
We'll follow you.
It's getting dark.
What's going
to happen to me?
All I can tell you is,
I will be here with you.
( vegetation rustling )
Mr. Tuvok, don't
make this difficult.
She's been frightened enough.
What she fears most
is being kept here
against her wishes.
This is a critical time.
I can't allow you
to interfere.
I regret it's
come to this.
You have found your crew member.
Now go.
I will not leave
without Tressa.
She has asked for my protection,
and I intend to provide it.
You simply don't understand
the harm you're doing.
This child wants to live.
We're going to do
whatever we can to help her.
It is not a choice.
This is her time.
Tressa has reached
the end of her life.
She has barely begun it.
She is 96 years old.
Tressa, these people
are outsiders.
They don't understand
how we live.
They see us as strange because
their aging process is reversed.
Please, you don't belong
with them.
I'm here to help you now.
No. Leave me alone.
It's perfectly natural
to be frightened.
You're taking a step
into the unknown.
The attendants would have
helped you prepare yourself.
You were never meant to face
this time alone.
We weren't alone.
Tuvok was here.
He stayed with us
and made us feel safe.
He told us there was no morrok
and that we shouldn't be afraid.
He took care of us...
even when we didn't behave
as well as Vulcan children.
He was right
about the morrok.
It only exists in stories.
At this age,
they become easily confused.
Their memories are clouded.
Near the end of life,
we reach
a stage of complete innocence.
We free ourselves from all
responsibilities to this life,
then we leave it peacefully.
Tressa doesn't seem to be ready.
Perhaps she needs more time.
That's not for you or me
to decide.
This is
a normal biological process,
which begins
the day we are created.
The energy contained
within our bodies
remains cohesive
for a limited number of years,
and then it is released.
Nothing can change that.
Nothing?
No.
It's the natural course of life.
Why was it so important
that Tressa stay here?
We believe this is where the
first spark of life was created.
We are all compelled
by a powerful instinct
to return here at the end,
to complete the cycle
and rejoin the infinite energy.
Tressa?
Do you feel it calling to you?
Tuvok?
She can offer you
better guidance than I.
You said you would protect me.
I cannot protect you
from the natural
conclusion of life,
nor would I try.
Vulcans consider death
to be the completion
of a journey.
There is nothing to fear.
I won't be afraid,
not if you're with me.
Tressa,
may this night
see you safely home.
Attending a child on the crysata
is an honorable role.
You have fulfilled it well.
The final moment of life
is the most sacred,
most private time.
I hope you can accept
my sincere apologies
for disturbing
your traditions.
Perhaps we've each misjudged
the other, Captain.
I would hate to let that ruin
any possibility of friendship
between our people.
We must leave them.
Tuvok, can your shuttle
make it back to Voyager?
Maybe we should wait for you.
No, I'll be fine.
We'll wait here
as long as you like.
I know it's time.
My only regret is leaving
my family, my grandson.
You remind me
of him sometimes.
You will still be with
them, in their thoughts,
as you will be in mine.