( playing "Jazz Impromptu" )
( pounding on wall )
Sorry!
Obviously, Ensign Baytart
doesn't appreciate music.
It's the darn fluid conduits
running through the walls.
They conduct sound.
You think when they designed
this thing, they would've--
The ship was built for combat
performance, Harry,
not musical performance.
Nobody figured
we'd be taking any long trips.
Where am I supposed to practice?
How about Cargobay?
KIM:
Bad acoustics.
We could get Baytart transferred
to the night shift.
Ha. Couldn't do that.
Could we?
( chuckles )
So now you have an excuse
to give your mother
why you didn't practice
while you were gone.
Look, I'm trying to prepare
for an important performance.
Oh, really?
Are we scheduled to rendezvous
with the Delta Quadrant
Symphony Orchestra?
No. Susan Nicoletti and I
have been working on
a new orchestral program
for the holodeck.
Lieutenant Nicoletti?
The one I've been chasing
for six months?
Cold hands, cold heart?
Not when she plays the oboe.
Chakotay
to all senior officers.
Please report to the Bridge.
You know, Harry,
I've always wanted to learn
how to play the drums.
( chuckles )
( majestic theme playing )
( console beeping )
I am picking up communication
satellites in orbit.
They're nonfunctional.
Mr. Paris, take us
in a little closer.
Mr. Kim, scan
the surface.
Captain, this used to be
a major trading spot.
How long ago?
I'm not sure exactly.
If I had to guess...
KIM:
EM signature
indicates
that a major solar flare
occurred here 19 years ago.
I'd say about 19 years...
more or less.
Looks like a glacial freeze.
Caused by a solar flare
that radically changed
the weather patterns.
KIM:
It did a lot
more than that.
They were hit by magnetic storms
and extreme levels of radiation.
Those glaciers are receding.
KIM:
The biosphere seems
to be recovering.
Did anyone survive?
KIM:
I'm scanning
the settlement.
There's evidence of
advanced technology--
warp reactors,
subspace transmitters--
but no life signs.
Maybe they saw it coming
and evacuated the planet.
TUVOK:
Indications are that any
attempt at an evacuation
would have been prevented
by the atmospheric disturbances.
What was
the estimated population?
TUVOK:
Approximately
400,000.
KIM:
Captain.
I'm picking up something
from the surface.
I think we're being hailed.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
I thought you said
there weren't any life signs.
There aren't.
I scanned the entire surface.
Must be an automated signal.
Let's hear it.
I am Viorsa, planner
for the Kohl settlement.
Your sensors have activated
this message.
By now, you must be aware
of the catastrophic disaster
that has destroyed our home.
A few of us
have managed to survive
in a state
of artificial hibernation,
programmed to end in 15 years
from the date
this was recorded.
At that time, when
the eco recovery has begun,
we will attempt
to rebuild our settlement.
Please do nothing
to interrupt our timetable.
Their timetable was supposed
to end four years ago.
Looks like they didn't make it.
Mr. Kim, wouldn't your scans
have picked up
suppressed metabolic activity?
I would think
so, Captain.
Unless...
Checking below the surface.
Nothing one kilometer down.
Two kilometers...
( console beeps )
Wait a minute.
I think I've got something.
2.3 kilometers down--
extremely faint bio-signatures.
Three humanoids.
Can you detect a malfunction
in their systems?
Something to explain why they
didn't wake up on schedule?
Not at this distance.
But I am picking up
two more humanoids
at the same location
who are dead.
Are there any
automated security systems?
We triggered
a "do not disturb" sign.
I don't want
to set off anything worse.
No weapons
of any kind, Captain.
It is safe to transport
the hibernation pods to Voyager,
if that is your intent.
It is.
Prepare to beam them
to Cargobay 1.
Mr. Kim, you're with me.
Janeway to Kes,
report to Cargobay 1.
Bring your medical gear.
Aye, Captain.
( soft theme playing )
Two humanoids dead.
Three humanoids in deep stasis.
Life signs
apparently stable.
Our messenger.
Did the system break down?
Not that I can see.
I'm not reading
any pathway failures
in the hibernation pods.
The circuitry all seems
to be functioning.
It looks like their brains
are interconnected
in a complex
sensory system
controlled by this computer.
( beeping )
According to these
indicators, Captain,
their minds
are active.
Active?
What do you mean?
The encephalographic
reading
suggests they're dreaming,
but there's some kind of
interactivity with the computer.
It's not just scanning
their brain functions.
It's sending a data stream
back to them, as well.
Could it be generating
an artificial environment
of some sort?
Artificial
environment?
Years ago, Starfleet
used a technology
to assist deep space travel
that kept the body in stasis,
but provided a mental landscape
to keep the mind
active and alert.
That sounds like
a pretty good way
to wait out
a planetary disaster.
For the moment,
it's as good a theory as any.
So, what went wrong?
Why are they
still in there?
KIM:
The system was supposed
to bring these people
out of hibernation
four years ago.
However, it wasn't left
entirely to the computer.
The programmers
obviously wanted
the people in the system
to decide for themselves
when it would be safe
to come out.
This was accomplished
by a subroutine
that periodically displayed
atmospheric conditions to them.
So, they should've known
years ago
that the biosphere
had recovered.
Exactly.
This subroutine has remained
available to these people
since it was activated
four years ago.
It's literally
an escape hatch.
Perhaps it has malfunctioned.
No. That's what's so odd
about this.
As far as I can tell,
it's working perfectly.
Then why don't they
get themselves out?
I don't know.
Maybe they like
it in there.
DOCTOR:
I don't think so.
Doctor?
The two victims died
from massive heart failure,
and there was evidence
of prior neural trauma.
I'm sorry.
What does that mean?
It could be evidence
of extreme...fear.
Maybe it was caused by the panic
that accompanies a heart attack.
The readings suggest an extended
period of mental stress.
Sounds like we ought
to get them out right away.
Surely, Commander,
you're not suggesting
we simply unplug them?
Why not?
Because you have three brains
whose survival
has depended upon careful
monitoring by a sophisticated
computer system for 19 years.
The doc is right.
I have no idea
how to disconnect them
without causing neural damage.
I just don't know
the system well enough.
They know the system.
Why don't we ask
them how to proceed?
How can we do that?
Implant a com-link
into their brains?
We already have a means
of communication--
the two unoccupied pods.
KIM:
We could add a backup
life support system,
using our own computer
and medical stasis technology.
The only way to help
those people is to go in
and find out from them
what's wrong.
I don't see any alternative.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Neither do I.
I'll be monitoring
your mental and
physical functions.
If we detect
any unusual activity,
you'll be transferred
onto our life support system
and resuscitated.
We've tapped into the system's
recall subroutine program.
I'll give you five minutes
to look around,
then I'm bringing you back.
Consider this a test run.
Understood.
Inducing primary stasis.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Autonomic nervous system link
is secure.
They're connecting
to the system.
TORRES:
Looks like
we made it.
How do you feel?
( exhales )
Normal.
( distant laughter )
( easy listening music
playing over speakers )
These must be characters
generated by the computer,
but I don't see our people.
Neither do I.
Uh, excuse me.
We're trying to find
some friends.
Well, that shouldn't
be difficult.
We're all friends here.
( all agreeing )
( laughter and music continue )
Oh, I'm sorry.
Ha. I didn't mean
to bump into you.
You're new.
Yes, we are.
Where are you from?
Another town.
There aren't any other towns.
We're not getting very far.
Perhaps I can help you.
You are looking
for friends?
That's right, three of them.
And when you find
these friends...?
We want to talk to them.
Why talk
when we can dance?
( dance music playing
over speakers )
( music ends )
Let's get out of here.
You got it.
( screams and laughter )
You!
( both grunting )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( chuckles )
Take him.
Harry.
Harry!
( mocking and laughter )
B'ELANNA:
Harry!
( crowd mocking )
Stop!
They're aliens!
And they won't be alone.
Kill them, and their shipmates
will shut down the program.
( characters exclaiming )
Let him go!
( crowd groans )
MALE:
We knew this would happen
someday-- that a ship
would find us.
It was only a matter of time.
Only a matter of time, yes.
MALE:
Who knows what kind
of people they are?
Who knows what will happen
to this world if you hurt them?
I do. I know.
( crowd chuckles )
Bring them here!
Bring them here, bring them
here, bring them here.
You're like me.
A little of this
and a little of that.
( chuckles )
Ooh! My, what a temper.
That's from your mother's side,
isn't it?
Yes. You see?
I know everything.
This is my world,
my festival,
and you're here
without an invitation.
What is going on? Who is he?
You will talk to me!
I speak for them.
And I speak for you, now.
Heh. You don't
understand that yet.
You don't accept it...
but you will.
Are you a life-form
or some kind of computer virus
that penetrated this system?
( crowd laughs )
♪ A virus, a virus ♪
♪ He thinks I am a virus ♪
♪ He thinks
I am a virus ♪
( laughs )
Well, perhaps
I'll be a virus today.
( sneezes )
Oh, this one's got a mind
full of technical
and operational
thoughts and ideas.
Harry knows viruses.
Stop this.
( soft theme playing )
I know you came here to get them
and take them away.
But if you do that,
we'll all disappear.
Disappear.
Because you're characters
created by this program.
And once their minds stop
interacting with the system,
you won't exist anymore.
Ah, see the technical mind
at work.
It seeks diagnostics,
data analysis.
Well, here's some more
data for your mind
to analyze
and diagnose, Harry.
Yes, I am merely
what has been created
and is being created
by his brain,
his brain, her
brain, and now...
yours, and yours.
( spits )
( beeping )
Wha...?
What's this doing here now?
This is your work.
That's our
wake-up call.
It's been a real pleasure,
but...we're leaving.
Come on.
If you leave, one
of them will die.
One of them
will die.
Try it and see.
If you leave...
he dies.
He can do it.
He's already killed
two of our colleagues.
How is that possible?
I cut off their heads.
But none of this is real.
CLOWN:
Of course it's real.
As real as a nightmare.
The two we found dead,
both suffered
from massive heart attacks.
Heart attack.
Now, what might cause
a heart attack? Hmm.
Unmanageable stress,
perhaps?
Unmanageable fear?
The fear of losing
a head, perhaps?
( tittering laughter )
You scared them
to death.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What's taking them so long?
Life signs are stable.
There's no interruption
in brain wave activity.
The recall subroutine
is functioning.
The window opened
for them on schedule.
Captain, the norepinephrine
levels are rising.
They're well above baseline.
Some of that
is to be expected,
but these levels indicate
abnormal stress.
All right.
I'm going to try to bring them
out with our backup systems.
KES:
Initiating
resuscitation.
The body temperature is rising.
( medical tricorder beeps )
JANEWAY:
What happened?
Their bodies are returning
to stasis condition, Captain.
Someone is terminating
the recall command
from inside the system.
CLOWN:
Very wise of you,
my technically
minded fellow.
Now, get rid of it completely.
It's an intrusion.
It's ruining the party.
That would be a mistake.
No mistake.
A mistake if you refuse.
You'd be missing an opportunity.
Trying to get the better of me?
Trying to trick me?
I know everything you know,
Harry Kim.
I know how much you miss Libby.
I know how you can never hit
that G-sharp
in the Mozart concerto.
Do you think I don't know
you're trying to defeat me?
Fine. So you know.
You'll also know that what I'm
about to tell you is the truth.
You'd be smart
to let one of us go.
Would I?
This is your chance to send
the outside world a message--
to tell them your demands.
I have only one demand--
to exist.
Then you'd better let us
tell them.
Otherwise, you run the risk
of our people
shutting down the whole system,
because I promise you,
they won't let us stay
in here for long.
( waltz playing over speakers )
How did this happen?
The system was designed
to be adaptive,
to observe and respond
to our thoughts
and adjust the environment
to our wishes.
Who wished him up?
It happened
over months
without our even realizing it.
All of us had fears
about survival, recovery.
We never anticipated
the computer would manifest
those fears into him.
Our only hope was
that someone like you
would come along and find us.
KIM:
It's almost as though
he can read our minds.
He seems to know
what we're thinking.
He's generated by the system,
and our brains are monitored
by the system,
so, yes, in a manner
of speaking, he can.
VIORSA:
But there is a delay
before he becomes aware
of what we're thinking.
It takes a few minutes
for our brain activity
to be processed by the system.
Well, I've come to a decision,
with the help of my friends.
You, leave. You, stay.
And tell your beloved
Captain Janeway
that if we die, they die,
including you, dear Harry--
you who becomes my best friend
as of today.
Because she would never
kill you, would she, Harry?
No. Why, she's like a dear
old mother to you, isn't she?
( chuckles )
Go!
Someone's activated
the recall subroutine.
KES:
Captain, it's
Lieutenant Torres.
Her body temperature is rising.
She should regain consciousness
in about...12 minutes.
At least, we'll finally
get the answers
to a few questions.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Well, let's start
with the obvious question.
If they're demanding
to exist,
can we find a way
to let them exist
in this artificial world
of theirs?
Not unless you're prepared
to leave one person
in stasis permanently.
DOCTOR:
I concur
with Lieutenant Torres.
The computer uses
bioneural feedback
from the participants' brains
to create the environment.
Doctor, is there a way
to speed up resuscitation?
Only by a few minutes.
Anything more, we'd be risking
serious brain damage.
Ten minutes would be
about the best we could do.
Ten minutes and all
the hostages could be killed.
Then it seems to me
our first order of business
should be to reduce
the number of hostages.
All we have to do now
is decide
how to negotiate with...
an emotion.
With a manifestation...
of fear.
Fear is the most primitive,
the most primordial
of biological
responses.
The ability
to recognize danger--
to fight it or run away from it.
That's what fear gives us,
but...when fear
holds you hostage...
how do you make it let go?
Maybe we should try
to make them laugh.
A good joke just...
uh, seems to make
fear dissolve.
Well, it does in me, anyway.
I think something
a little more responsive
to The Clown's demand.
B'Elanna, maybe you can come up
with a way
to modify the system
so it can run
without bioneural interaction.
How do we negotiate
without sending in
another hostage?
Good question.
We have to come up with
a safer method of communication.
VIORSA:
I regret very much
what has happened to you.
You came to help.
You didn't deserve this.
( haunting synth music
playing over speakers )
I regret so many things.
Look.
We don't have time
for regret.
My people are working
on a way, right now,
to get us out of here,
and we have to help
them if we can.
You'll leave hope behind
after a few months of this.
( maniacal laugh )
Why does he do it?
We're his canvas...
his blocks of marble.
With us, he practices
his ghastly art.
CLOWN:
Thinking about escape,
are we, Harry?
Naughty, naughty.
I don't like those thoughts.
We're going to have to do
something about them.
He's new. He can't help
thinking about getting out.
He can!
You don't think
about it anymore.
Oh, but he's new...
and you're old.
New and old...
old and new.
Well, then, the answer
is to simply...
make you old, Harry.
( laughs )
Are you afraid of
growing old, Harry?
Is that
what you fear--
being cared for by nurses?
Time for your medicine.
You don't like
being helpless, do you, Harry?
You like to take care
of yourself.
Yes, I know
how you hate
to feel
like the baby on the crew.
( laughing maniacally )
( crying )
Ho-ho-ho-ho-ho!
Oh, what's
the matter, Harry?
Ooh, does my costume
frighten you, huh? Ooh!
Coochie-coo.
( Clown laughs )
Yeah. Oh, look
at little Harry fly!
Whoo!
Whoo! There he goes!
Whee! Ha-ha-ha.
All right, that's enough.
( crying continues )
( chuckling
maniacally )
This is not reality.
It's an illusion.
When your only reality
is an illusion,
then illusion is a reality.
Like the man said:
"The only thing we have
to fear is fear itself."
Oh, I thought we were
gonna be friends.
Didn't want to do
this, Harry.
No, I didn't want
to bring this up
in front of the others,
but I know what
really scares you.
I know when you were nine
and your parents took
you to that colony--
the radiation disaster?
Humanitarian mission?
You visited a hospital!
You remember.
( laughs )
No.
You wandered off
by yourself
where you weren't
supposed to be.
The only thing we have to fear
is fear itself.
You saw people
and things
you weren't
supposed to see--
sick and dying...
Keep repeating:
"The only thing we
have to fear
is fear itself!"
ALL:
"The only thing we have to fear
is fear itself."
And how about:
"There's no place like home!
There's no place
like home!"
( laughing maniacally )
Try clicking your heels
together three times.
Oh, but your legs
are restrained, aren't they?
Just like that little girl
you saw on the operating table?
The doctor called
for a scalpel...
She looked at you,
her face filled
with fear.
Fear...
fear.
Fear.
( shouting ):
Do you remember?
( screaming ):
No!
DOCTOR:
Excuse me.
You're not holding
that properly.
Correct positioning
of the index finger
is necessary
for optimal dexterity.
( scalpel clatters )
Who are you?
I'm Captain Janeway's
representative.
I'm here to negotiate
with you.
Are you well, Mr. Kim?
I'm starting
to feel better.
CLOWN:
You're different.
I don't know anything about you.
You're not on the system.
I would be pleased to tell you
all about myself
at a more appropriate time.
For now, suffice it to say
that I am here
by a miracle of technology.
Now, let's get down
to the issues, shall we?
How am I supposed to negotiate
if I don't know
what you're thinking?
I have a very trustworthy face.
My Captain
is prepared
to give you exactly
what you ask for
under the condition you release
all the hostages.
( spluttering laugh )
Release the hostages?
We would provide continuing
input from a simulated brain.
A computer model
that would generate...
Simulated brain? Simulated?
I myself have a com---
It won't work.
It's a lie. Tell 'em, Harry.
I don't know that
for sure.
Liar! Viorsa! Get over here.
Tell him.
It might require
a recalibration
of the optronic pathways.
Liar! After all this time,
do you think
I can't tell when you lie?
The simulated brain...
Would leave me at your mercy!
No. They stay.
The Captain is prepared
to risk the lives
of the hostages
rather than leave them
under your control.
Who is she to tell me
what I have to do?
She's the one out there with
the "off" switch in her hand.
She would never kill Harry.
I'd rather die than spend
my life in here with you.
She knows that.
I won't let them go.
A compromise.
Let some of them go.
No.
We've studied your system.
You only need one to survive.
And if that one gets sick
and dies?
No! I need them all.
Now go away!
And tell your Captain Janeway
I'm disappointed.
I expected more from her.
If we could just--
CLOWN:
Go away!
CROWD:
Go away! Go away!
( sighs )
I'll be back.
Go away!
CROWD:
Go away! Go away! Go away!
Well, I'm sorry I don't live up
to his expectations.
What's your opinion
of him, doctor?
Unstable...
unpredictable.
Everything you'd
expect from "fear."
Captain, the longer
we allow this to continue,
the more likely it is
that he
will take his frustrations
out on the hostages.
I agree.
And I can't allow that
to happen.
We're going to have to mount
some kind of rescue mission.
Doctor, if we do simply
disconnect the hostages...
There would certainly
be brain damage.
How much damage?
Could you possibly
repair it?
Possibly? Yes.
Would Mr. Kim still be able
to hold his clarinet
when I was done?
Possibly.
The brain is such
an interesting organ.
Could we switch over
to a simulated brain
without The Clown
noticing it?
Oh, he'd notice.
He was very smart to reject
the whole notion
of a simulated brain.
It just wouldn't be the same.
There is no way
an artificial intelligence
can replace actual
brain functions.
I'll choose not to take
that personally, Lieutenant.
For what it's worth, Mr. Viorsa
suggested there would be a way
to make a simulated brain
function in this system.
He suggested it would take...
a "recalibration
of the optronic pathways."
I don't know what he could
have been talking about.
The optronic pathways
have nothing to do
with the neural interface.
It doesn't make any sense.
TUVOK:
Then, perhaps he had
another reason for saying it.
How do the optronic
pathways function
in this system, B'Elanna?
They-- They control
the basic elements
of the environment,
access data banks
that were programmed
when the system
was created.
If we interrupt
the optronic pathways,
we could disassemble
that entire world
and its characters,
piece by piece.
If we can't remove the hostages
from the environment,
then we might be able
to remove the environment
from the hostages.
How did Viorsa manage
to communicate this
without The Clown
knowing about it?
Perhaps it was because
The Clown's attention
was divided at the time.
And you're going
to continue
to provide him with
distractions, doctor.
B'Elanna, how long will it take
to block these pathways?
I'm not sure how many there are,
Captain.
And I'll have to do it manually,
because we don't know
how to deprogram the system.
You'll only have
a few minutes at best.
Once "fear" knows
what we're up to,
it'll be a race against time
to save the lives
of those hostages.
Bravo! Bravo!
Go away!
I want to be alone.
You're ruining the festival.
Don't be a poop!
I can't help it.
I'm feeling sorry
for myself.
Well, don't
take it out on us.
Take it out on them.
You people--
you wonderful
people--
my friends...
( sniffles )
You do know
how to make a man
feel better, don't you?
Okay, then, what
shall we play?
The insect game.
Yes, yes.
You again?
You're the one
who ruined my mood.
You and your sweet Captain.
My sweet Captain
has a new offer to make.
No simulated brains.
I want real brains.
The Captain is prepared to give
you...a cloaking device.
I already have
a cloaking device.
Thank you anyway.
DOCTOR:
I'm talking about a device
that would shield you
from being detected by any
other interstellar visitors.
( soft theme playing )
( instrument whirring )
There are almost 40 pathways
to disable, Captain,
but I should be able
to get it done
in under two minutes.
Good.
Let's get started.
We will return
your entire computer system
to the subterranean locale
where we found it.
With the help
of Mr. Kim,
and a team of
Starfleet engineers,
it will be
an easy matter
to install
the cloaking device,
which will ensure
your safety
for the foreseeable future.
Harry, is this possible?
Yes.
I don't know
if I believe you.
I don't know yet...
but I'll know soon
if you're telling the truth.
You can't fool me.
( chuckles )
( suspenseful theme playing )
What does she want in return?
And don't say the hostages,
because I'm not
giving them up.
You have to understand
that the Captain's
primary concern
is the safety of the hostages.
She's such a warm
and noble person.
I'd love her to come
to one of my parties someday.
What if I promise to take
really good care of my guests?
We could be more
than friends.
We could be...colleagues.
( chuckles )
I'm really not
such a bad fella.
What's happening?
CLOWN:
You tricked me!
It's an attack!
Red Alert! Red Alert!
You-- You warned them.
You told them how
it could be done!
Take him!
No, please! No!
Twenty-two.
More than halfway
there, B'Elanna.
KES:
Captain, it's Viorsa.
His norepinephrine levels
are rising sharply.
No, please!
I didn't do anything!
What is it?
Some kind of
protection device.
I'm locked out.
I'll have to disable it.
( taunting shouts and laughter )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( grunts )
( growling )
Viorsa's norepinephrine
levels are critical.
Just ten more pathways.
( piercing scream )
( all screaming )
( wailing )
( woman screaming )
( steady tone sounds )
He's dead!
Massive heart failure.
( insistent beeping )
Captain, this one's
norepinephrine levels
are approaching critical.
CLOWN:
You're next! You're next!
( Clown laughing )
Restore the entire program.
We've lost.
We've won.
We've won. We've won!
Start the music.
Celebration.
Celebration. Celebration.
Your decision
to capitulate
saved the lives of the other
hostages, Captain.
You should take some
comfort from that.
I don't.
Have I misjudged him somehow?
Is there another way
to reach him?
Isn't there more to "fear"
than a simple demand to exist?
Why do people enjoy
dangerous sports
or holodeck adventures
with the safety off?
Why, after all these centuries,
do children still ride
on roller coasters?
Fear can provide
pleasure.
To seek fear is to seek
the boundaries of one's
sensory experience.
But what does fear seek...
at the end of the ride?
( raucous music
playing over speakers )
You understand,
don't you, Harry,
that we will have
to punish you
for your Captain's
little trick?
To the winner go the spoils,
and you are the spoils,
after all.
We can talk
about that later.
For now, enjoy yourself.
( music and laughter stop )
Well, you
certainly know
how to bring
a party to a halt.
I don't get out very much.
CLOWN:
I bet.
The Captain has sent me
with an ultimatum.
Ultimatum? Ultimatum.
She would give me an ultimatum?
( all laughing heartily )
Did Napoleon give an ultimatum
after Waterloo?
Did Chulak of Romulus
give an ultimatum
after his defeat
at Galorndon Core?
We won. We give
the ultimatums around here.
The Captain is prepared
to shut down the system
one minute from now,
if you don't agree to her terms.
And scramble the brains of all
my guests, including Harry?
I don't think so.
Fifty-two seconds.
She is willing
to risk
brain damage
to the hostages,
but she will end this, and end
this now, one way or another.
What are her-- her terms?
Forty-three seconds.
She will allow you to keep
one person on the system.
The other hostages
must be released.
One?
Never! I won't agree.
You have 30 seconds
to avoid termination.
I need more time...
time to think.
Two. Let me keep two.
Twenty seconds.
There is another provision.
The one hostage
you will be allowed to keep
is Captain Janeway herself.
She...would choose
to be with me?
Your time is up.
Your answer, please.
Yes.
Captain, this is the doctor.
I've returned to Sickbay.
Please turn to your emergency
medical holographic channel.
Did he accept?
Yes, Captain.
Perfect. Good
work, doctor.
Would you like me
to return and supervise
the evacuation of the hostages?
I don't think that'll be
necessary, but you could
help with the preparations
at this end. Janeway out.
B'ELANNA:
We're finished here, Captain.
Initiate the recall subroutine
and prepare to begin
resuscitation.
Kes, give me a hand
getting hooked up to all this.
( haunting music playing
over speakers )
CLOWN:
Sparkling.
I want everything sparkling
for her arrival.
Sparkling. Ha-ha-ha.
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Harry, not so fast.
They can't have you
until I have her.
No more tricks.
She's coming.
I can feel the system
beginning to scan her brain.
Hmm...this really
is such an extraordinary
gesture she's making.
I am so moved.
( blows nose )
You don't quite believe it
yourself, do you?
The Captain would
sacrifice herself
to save the hostages.
Sacrifice
herself?
You can be so cruel, Harry.
You don't appreciate
my hospitality.
( suspenseful theme playing )
You're here.
You're actually here.
I don't believe it.
The arrangement was that
the others would be released.
You show remarkable trust,
Captain.
How could you be so sure
I would keep my word?
I've known fear.
It's a very healthy thing
most of the time.
You warn us of danger,
remind us of our limits,
protect us
from carelessness.
I've learned
to trust fear.
Finally, someone
who appreciates me.
Am I blushing?
Let them go.
Yes. Yes, of course.
You may depart.
Farewell, my friends.
Do come back
and visit.
I'll always be here.
( gasps )
The recall subroutine
has been activated.
Body temperatures
are rising.
Initiating
all backup systems.
The hostages should
regain consciousness
in less than ten minutes.
We'll get you out
of here, Captain.
I promise.
That won't be
necessary, Mr. Kim,
but thank you.
I can't wait
to get to know you...
to make you a part of me.
As I understand it,
it takes a few minutes
before you become aware
of my thoughts.
Is that true?
An eternity of anticipation.
And then what happens?
And then the fun begins.
All systems functioning
as anticipated.
Resuscitation
entering final warming.
Bio-functions
are returning to normal.
Their own hearts
are taking over.
They don't need supplemental
life support any longer.
Would you be
honest with me?
Fear is the most honest
of all emotions, Captain.
You really want
this to end
as much as I do,
don't you?
Now, now, don't even think
about leaving.
I'm not going to let you go--
not after all this.
Mirror?
Don't we make a beautiful
couple, Captain?
I'm not Captain Janeway.
Could have fooled me.
I'm afraid I did.
Pardon?
I'm nothing more
than a holographic image
of Captain Janeway,
sent here by the same
technique they used
to send their doctor.
I've been programmed
to respond to you
as Kathryn Janeway would.
But-- But-- I-I feel you.
Y-you're on the system.
She is on the system,
yes, but not in stasis.
Captain Janeway and her
crew modified the pods,
so that she could be
connected to the system
without having to enter
this environment.
The goal was to let you
sense her brain activity
without putting her
in actual jeopardy.
You will be able
to confirm
what I'm telling you
as soon as you become
aware of her thoughts.
You know as well as I do
that fear only exists
for one purpose--
to be conquered.
She tricked me.
Did she?
Or was a part of you actually
hoping to be defeated?
Isn't that why you allowed
Captain Janeway to come here?
Because you sensed
she had the power
to subdue you?
No.
She lied.
It was very un-Starfleet of her.
Starfleet Captains
don't easily succumb...to fear.
What will become of us?
Of me?
Like all fear,
you eventually...vanish.
I'm afraid.
I know.
Drat.
( majestic theme playing )