JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49655.2.
Our sensors have located
a variety of flower
which may prove to be
a valuable
nutritional supplement.
I've sent Mr. Neelix and
Mr. Tuvok to collect samples.
( inhaling deeply )
Whoa!
Smell that air, Mr. Vulcan!
Look at that sky!
Oh, it's an exhilarating day,
isn't it?
As you well know by now,
Mr. Neelix,
I do not experience
exhilaration.
Oh, let's not quibble
about semantics.
A breeze is blowing,
the sun is shining.
It's beautiful.
The weather is certainly
adequate for our purposes.
Adequate?
You know something?
You're acting
more "Tuvokian"
than usual this morning.
I am who I am,
Mr. Neelix.
It is impossible for me to be
more or less like myself.
There you go with
the semantics again.
But you know what
I'm talking about.
I'm afraid I don't.
Well, then, I'll
explain it to you.
You're a nature lover,
aren't you?
I appreciate nature, yes.
It's one of the things that
you and I have in common.
And here we are,
on a perfect day,
foraging for an exceptionally
lovely variety of orchid--
your favorite flower--
and all you can say
about the experience
is that it's adequate.
I just... I don't see why
you're not having fun.
We are not here
to have fun.
We are here
to collect samples.
Why? Is there
some regulation
that says we can't do
both at the same time?
I know.
Why don't, why don't
we sing a song
while we toil, hm?
It'll cheer you up.
I've been studying Vulcan music.
Uh... do you know
that lovely tune that starts:
♪ O starless night ♪
♪ Of boundless black... ♪
That "lovely tune"
is a traditional funeral dirge.
I know,
but it was the most cheerful
song I could find
in the Vulcan
database.
Come on, Tuvok,
join me.
♪ O starless night ♪
♪ Of boundless black... ♪
( chuckling )
Mr. Neelix...
Yes?
Do you think
you could possibly behave
a little less...
like yourself?
( sighs )
Are Neelix and Tuvok
back from the surface?
Not yet. We're having some
trouble with the transporter.
TORRES:
Captain...
there's a minor glitch in
the molecular imaging scanners.
Ensign Kim should have it up
and running
in a few minutes.
Try narrowing
the annular confinement beam.
( console beeping )
How's that?
Let's try it again.
Kim to away team.
Sorry for the delay.
We're ready
to bring you back.
TUVOK:
Acknowledged.
Energize.
There's something
wrong, sir.
I'm only getting
one pattern.
Tuvok or Neelix?
I don't think
it's either of them.
Abort.
It's too late.
[♪♪♪]
Kim to Security.
Intruder alert,
Transporter Room 1.
Identify yourself.
I'm Lieutenant Tuvok.
And I'm Neelix.
Sir, according to
the bio-scanners, he's right.
Somehow their patterns
have merged.
I think the logical thing
is for me to go to Sick Bay.
And you recognize
all of us?
Of course.
Doctor, Captain Janeway,
Ensign Kim...
Kes.
DOCTOR:
My scans indicate
that all biological matter
was merged on a molecular level.
Proteins, enzymes,
DNA sequences.
The man you see
before you
is literally a
fusion of two men.
But he's surprisingly healthy,
considering the circumstances.
All vital signs are stable.
What's the last
thing you remember?
I... we... that is to say,
Tuvok and Neelix,
we had just finished
gathering the samples.
We were beaming back
to the ship.
The next thing I knew,
I was standing
on the transporter pad
as you see me now.
DOCTOR:
I'm also picking up
traces
of a third genetic pattern.
It appears
to be plant-based.
TUVIX:
The orchids.
We had collected several dozen
samples of orchids.
They were in our sample
containers when we beamed up.
Well, they're part
of your genetic structure now.
But they
don't appear
to be affecting
your biochemistry.
Torres said you were
having trouble with
the molecular imaging scanners.
That's right.
Maybe this alien plant life
affected
the scanners in some way.
Possibly. I'll know more
after we've run a diagnostic
on the biofilters
and transporter logs.
Get on it.
In the meantime, I'll send
an away team in a shuttlecraft
to collect fresh samples
of the orchid for further study.
Doctor, let me know as soon
as you have something more.
Yes, Captain.
Kes, take our patient
to the Science Lab
and perform a full
bio-spectral analysis.
I'll start examining
the genetic data.
( door opens, closes )
This situation must be
very difficult for you, Kes.
Perhaps it would be easier
if someone else
administered these tests.
Thank you for your concern,
but I'll be fine.
This scan is very delicate,
so try to remain still
for the next 20 minutes.
I'll do my best.
Don't worry.
We're going to figure it out.
Oh, I'm not worried.
I couldn't be in better hands.
This crew, you're
consummate professionals.
You're my friends.
My family.
So worrying would be illogical,
don't you think?
Would you mind if I
asked you some questions
about what
you're going through?
Not at all.
Well, do you feel
as if you're thinking
with two minds--
two separate minds?
Are Neelix and Tuvok
inside of you, talking to me,
talking to each other?
If you mean am I suffering
from some form
of multiple personality
disorder, I don't think so.
I do have the memories
of both men,
but I seem to have
a single consciousness.
You must find me
very odd, Kes.
No, of course not.
Try to keep still.
So... what should
I call you?
Ah, a name.
I hadn't thought of that.
What an intriguing question.
I can see why the Doctor
is finding it
so difficult to choose one.
A name can have
a significant effect
upon a person's
sense of identity.
I've got it.
What?
Why don't you call me...
Neevok.
Wait.
This is better.
How about Tuvix?
Tuvix it is.
I'm so glad you're here to help
me through this, sweeting.
I'm sorry.
It was instinct.
Why don't we finish the scan.
DOCTOR:
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Extensive microcellular scans
on the merged humanoid
have, thus far, yielded
no clues to either a cause
or a method of separation.
Ah, Captain, so good
of you to come.
How are you feeling?
I feel well.
You might even say...
exhilarated.
I'm glad to hear it.
Well, that's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
In the past 24 hours,
I've undergone
rigorous diagnostic testing,
submitted to an extensive
psychological profile
and I've been
poked and prodded
in organs that I
didn't even know I had.
While all this testing
may no doubt
be necessary...
frankly, I'm restless.
To tell you the truth,
we could use a little help
in the Mess Hall.
And I'd be glad
to give you a hand.
But...
after careful consideration,
I've decided that the most
sensible thing for me to do
is to resume
the tactical post.
Tactical?
Remember, Captain,
I do possess Tuvok's
knowledge and expertise,
and while I have no doubt
that the crew misses
Neelix's cooking,
you need your most
experienced Tactical Officer.
That's me.
If I may, Captain.
Mr. Tuvix...
Tuvix?
Apparently, that's what
he likes to be called.
Mr. Tuvix is, indeed,
in perfect health.
And since I've collected
all the data I need,
there's no reason I can't
continue my investigation
without him
for the time being.
And, according to my tests,
he's quite correct
when he says that he possesses
Tuvok's knowledge and expertise.
He also possesses
Tuvok's irritating sense
of intellectual superiority
and Neelix's
annoying ebullience.
I would be very grateful to you
if you would assign him
some duty.
Any duty...
somewhere else.
Well... Mr. Tuvix...
I'm not ready to assign you
to the Bridge just yet,
but why don't you
join the senior staff
for our noon briefing,
and we'll see
how it goes from there.
Captain, has anyone
ever told you
that you are as fair-minded
as you are lovely?
As a matter of fact,
Neelix has told me
that occasionally.
And if you really do
possess his memories...
you'd know that flattery
will get you nowhere.
The transporter
was functioning normally.
Biofilters, pattern buffers,
everything checked out.
What about the problem
with the molecular
imaging scanners?
According to
the transporter logs,
they were optimal at
the time of transport.
It was a perfectly routine
beam-out sequence.
No anomalies,
no power overloads,
no malfunctions.
Our scans of the planet's
surface and atmosphere
don't show anything
out of the ordinary.
CHAKOTAY:
There's no evidence
of any type
of alien interference.
Frankly, Captain,
we're at a loss.
And the orchids, Kes?
Have you found anything
unusual about them?
Commander Chakotay brought back
a few samples on the shuttle
and I ran
a biochemical analysis.
They contain the same elements
as many plants: chloroplasts,
lysosomal enzymes,
cytoplasmic proteins,
but there's
nothing unusual.
There's never been an accident
like this recorded
in the entire history
of transporter technology.
I'm not willing to accept it
as a random malfunction.
Captain, I recommend we program
a holodeck simulation,
try recreating the accident.
Sex.
I beg your pardon?
What I mean to say is--
and I apologize
for cutting you off, Commander--
I think we're
on the wrong track.
Kes... you said that the flowers
you examined
contained lysosomal enzymes.
That's right.
According to Tuvok's
botanical research,
the presence
of lysosomal enzymes
could be evidence
of symbiogenesis.
Symbiogenesis?
JANEWAY:
Symbiogenesis is a rare
reproductive process.
Instead of pollination
or mating,
symbiogenetic organisms merge
with a second species.
Andorian amoebae,
for instance--
they're able to merge with
other single-celled organisms
to form a third
unique species.
A hybrid.
Like you.
Exactly.
It's an interesting idea,
but we're talking about
microcellular organisms here.
I've never heard
of symbiogenesis occurring
in a species as complex
as a humanoid.
Actually, Captain,
when you think about it,
Neelix and Tuvok
were broken down
to a microcellular level
during transport-- DNA,
protein, all in a state
of molecular flux.
And if the enzymes that
cause symbiogenesis
interacted with their DNA
while they were in
the matter stream,
it might've caused
their patterns to merge.
Like an Andorian amoeba.
Just like that,
Tuvix is born.
It's the best theory
I've heard so far.
It's the only theory
And it's worth investigating.
Mr. Paris, take a shuttle
to the planet
and collect additional
flower specimens.
Yes, ma'am, but I'd recommend
waiting until morning.
The weather on the planet
can get
pretty nasty
at night.
Very well.
You'll depart at 600 hours.
Good work, Mr. Tuvix.
Kes.
Oh, hello.
Hello.
Do you need something?
Actually, I was wondering
if you'd like
to join me for dinner.
Well, I, uh...
You've already eaten?
Well, no.
You're not hungry?
Actually...
If memory serves me,
Wednesday's the day
that Neelix always cooked
Trellan crepes--
your favorite meal?
That's right.
Well, why break
with tradition
just because of a little
transporter accident?
( laughs )
Somebody's eggs are burning!
WOMAN:
Those are mine.
Can you flip them for me?
I can't find a spatula.
WOMAN:
Just... try
tossing them.
Why don't you
have a seat?
I'll be with you
in a minute.
Do you mind telling me
what's going on here, crewman?
We're making dinner.
I see.
All right, everybody out!
On whose authority?
Chief of Security
or Head Chef--
take your pick.
Out, out, out!
( Tuvix clapping )
TUVIX:
Come, come.
Out!
( laughing )
So you really enjoyed
the crepes?
Oh, they were
absolutely delicious.
Don't you think Neelix
always made them
a little too spicy?
These were a little
different than usual.
Did you change the recipe?
Only slightly.
I thought more moderate
seasoning would allow
the flavor of the mushrooms
to come through.
I loved the mushrooms.
I'm glad.
I can't believe
how disorganized
this galley was.
It's a wonder Neelix
ever found anything.
He says he has a system.
But I guess you
already know that.
I admire your strength, Kes.
Why do you say that?
I know I'm not Neelix,
but I can posit
with complete certainty
that if the situation
were reversed--
if suddenly he found himself
without you in his life--
he'd be absolutely lost.
I have to go.
Thanks again for dinner.
Good morning, Captain.
Commander.
You're here bright and early,
Lieutenant.
Actually, I've been here
since 0400 hours.
I wanted to work on that
proximity detector glitch
in the security subroutine.
And how's it going?
I managed to correct it.
Tuvok said it could
take up to ten days
to check out all
the possible problems.
How'd you fix
it so fast?
I had a hunch.
"A hunch"?
That's correct.
You'll have a report
on your desk
first thing
this afternoon.
Kim to Mr. Tuvix.
Tuvix here.
We're just about ready
to start the transporter tests
if you'd like to join us.
I'm on my way.
Excuse me, Captain.
Well, he's certainly
fitting in, isn't he?
There's an old axiom:
"The whole is never greater
than the sum of its parts."
I think Tuvix might be
disproving that notion.
Give me the flowers
from the airponics bay.
Here you go.
One prize-winning
chrysanthemum...
one garden-variety
clematis...
and last but not least...
one symbiogenetic
alien orchid.
I never thought
that botanical science class
would come in so handy.
Torres to Transporter Room 1.
We're ready down here.
Acknowledged.
Energizing.
We've made over 100 attempts
to reverse the symbiogenesis
using the medical
transporter,
and each time, this has been
the unfortunate result--
complete
cellular collapse.
The genetic codes
of the chrysanthemum
and the clematis
are so scrambled
that the targeting
scanners
can't recognize
the original patterns.
I suppose it would be
like trying to extract
the flour, eggs
and water
after you'd baked
the cake.
Obviously, in the
case of Mr. Tuvix,
we're dealing with a much more
complex organism than a flower.
In effect, we're talking
about recreating
two humanoid life-forms
without so much
as a single discrete strand
of DNA to start with.
Are you saying I'm going
to be this way forever?
I am an incredibly
skilled doctor
and I will continue
to pursue
a safe and effective
treatment until I find one...
but I won't lie to you.
I'm not optimistic.
It could take months,
even years,
to find a solution.
And we must face
the possibility
that this condition is simply...
untreatable.
I feel as though
I've lost two patients.
I'm sorry.
I'll inform the rest
of the crew.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
It's all right.
Um, please...
sit down.
Ocampan prayer tapers.
For Tuvok and Neelix?
It's funny...
if something happened to Tuvok,
if Neelix were here,
he'd be the first person
to comfort me.
And if I lost Neelix...
Tuvok would be
the first person
to guide me spiritually.
Now I don't have either of them.
You have me, Kes.
Thank you.
But...
I remind you
of what you've lost.
It's not your fault.
I know, and I'm trying
to accept who I am now.
Captain Janeway tells me
there's a place
for me on this ship...
but I can't help feeling like...
like some sort of impostor.
Maybe we can help
each other get through this.
That's what
I've been hoping.
I know this is going to sound
very strange to you...
perhaps even illogical...
since, in a way, we've only
known each other a few days.
But I want you to know...
I love you, Kes.
But I hardly know you.
A-And besides, what about...
what about Tuvok's wife,
for one thing?
He was completely
devoted to her.
What happens
when Voyager
gets back home?
Are you just going
to forget her?
I could never forget T'Pel.
I carry Tuvok's love
for her inside me
and I would never ask you
to forget Neelix.
How can you talk this way?
Because
I carry Neelix's love for you
inside me, as well,
and I always will.
You heard
the Doctor.
It could be years
before he finds a way to bring
Tuvok and Neelix back--
if ever.
For you,
that might be a lifetime.
Please go.
I'm sorry.
I should've controlled
my emotions.
All I really came to say
is that I'll be here for you
if you need me.
( door chimes )
Kes.
Captain.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have bothered you this late.
I'll, uh, talk to you
tomorrow.
Actually, I was having
trouble sleeping.
I could use some company.
Would you like
some hot tea?
Please, sit down.
I was just looking over
some old letters Tuvok sent me
when he was temporarily
assigned to Jupiter Station.
Most people would say
his writing is cold,
analytical, detached, but...
I've always found it to be...
concise, efficient...
...thoughtful.
I hear his voice
when I read the words.
And Neelix...
I'd become
so fond of him, Kes.
I can't imagine what
you're going through.
I wanted to talk
to you about Tuvix.
He came to see me
this afternoon.
Oh?
He said... he said
that he loves me.
I suppose I can see
how that's possible,
given the circumstances.
I wasn't sure what to say.
At first I was angry,
but I know how he's
trying to comfort me
and I know that he
feels alone, too.
To tell the truth,
he's a wonderful person.
Do you have feelings
for him, too, Kes?
No, I don't.
I mean, how could I?
I still love Neelix...
and I'm not ready
to give up on him,
no matter what the Doctor says.
I know how you feel.
You're experiencing
what people on this crew
have been going through
since we first got stranded
in this Quadrant.
Do we accept
that we're separated
from our loved ones forever?
Or do we hold on to the hope
that, someday,
we'll be with them again?
What do you do, Captain?
Oh... I struggle with it
every day.
Sometimes, I'm full
of hope and optimism.
Other times...
( clears throat )
I dream about being with Mark...
...and it's so real.
Then, when I wake up
and realize it's just a dream,
I'm terribly discouraged.
In those moments,
it's impossible to deny
just how far away he really is.
And, uh...
I know that, someday,
I may have to accept that he's
not part of my life anymore.
So, are you saying
that I should just accept
that Neelix isn't a part
of my life anymore?
I would never tell you
or anyone else
to give up hope, Kes.
I think the best thing
you can do now...
is give yourself time.
Thank you, Captain.
I'll go now and
let you sleep.
My door is always
open to you, Kes.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49678.4.
It's been two weeks
since the transporter accident
that created Mr. Tuvix
and, while it's still
not entirely clear
that he's with us permanently,
he's certainly been doing
his best to settle in.
The crew seems to be growing
accustomed to his presence,
and he's proving to be
a very able Tactical Officer
who isn't afraid
to express his opinions.
While he's forging
relationships
with many of the officers,
he seems to be keeping a
respectful distance from Kes,
allowing her to adjust
to the circumstances
on her own terms.
As for my relationship
with Tuvix,
I've found him
to be an able advisor,
who skillfully uses humor
to make his points.
And although I feel
a bit guilty saying it,
his cooking is better
than Neelix's.
My taste buds
are definitely happy
to have him around.
( playing medium tempo melody)
DOCTOR:
Sick Bay to Ensign Kim.
Please turn to your emergency
medical holographic channel.
How can I help you, Doc?
Suppose I found
a radioisotope
that could selectively
attach itself
to specific
DNA sequences.
Could the surgical transporters
be reprogrammed
to lock on to those
enhanced sequences
and separate them
from the remaining DNA?
Well, I think so,
but we'd have to modify
the molecular imaging scanners,
and find a way to compensate for
the higher levels of radiation.
Thank you, Ensign.
Wait a second.
What's going on?
It's pure speculation
at this point.
I'll let you know
when I've learned more.
This is about Tuvix, isn't it?
I'm on my way.
Eight ball, corner pocket.
That's game again, Commander.
We've created a monster.
Best out of five?
( door opens, closes )
Would you mind if we finished
this later, Commander?
Not at all.
Hi.
( clears throat )
How have you been?
Good days and bad days.
You?
Me, too.
Listen, I'm sorry I've been
so distant lately.
Kes, you don't owe
me an explanation.
I've been doing
a lot of thinking.
And I'm hoping
that we can be friends.
I would like that very much.
And I'd like our
friendship to grow.
You would?
Yes.
But it's going to take time.
I'm not going anywhere.
Doctor to Lieutenant Tuvix.
Tuvix here.
Please report
to Sick Bay immediately.
DOCTOR:
Until late
in the 21st century,
physicians administered
barium to patients
with certain
gastrointestinal disorders.
The radioactive properties
of the barium
made the lining
of the intestines visible,
with a primitive imaging
technology called X rays.
Instead of barium, we've
come up with a radioisotope
that attaches itself
to the DNA of one
of the merged species,
but not the other.
Then we simply beam out
the selected DNA,
and segregate
the two merged species.
You see these?
They used to be
a single merged flower.
And you can use
this same process?
It will require
a more detailed reprogramming
of the transporter,
but, yes, I believe
we can restore
Mr. Tuvok
and Mr. Neelix.
That's wonderful.
Isn't that wonderful?
I assure you,
Mr. Tuvix,
there's nothing
to worry about.
We've accounted
for every variable.
Except one.
I don't want to die.
It's funny...
if we'd had the ability
to separate Tuvok and Neelix
the moment Tuvix came aboard...
I wouldn't have hesitated.
Of course not.
But now...
in the past few weeks...
he's begun to make a life
for himself on this ship.
He's taken on
responsibilities...
made friends...
I count myself
as one of them.
So, at what point did
he become an individual
and not a transporter
accident?
( door chimes )
( sighs )
Come in.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
Yes, Mr. Tuvix.
Please, sit down.
I feel as though
I've been dragged in front
of the Numirian Inquisition.
Will you excuse us, Commander?
( door opens, closes )
We've just
been discussing
the unfortunate...
predicament
that we're all facing,
and I thought it was important
to get your perspective
before making a decision.
Are you suggesting that this
is your decision to make?
I am the Captain of this ship.
Begging your pardon, Captain,
it's my life.
Isn't it my decision?
Aren't there two other lives
to consider here?
What about Tuvok and Neelix--
two voices that we
can't hear right now?
As Captain,
I must be their voice,
and I believe
they would want to live.
But they are living, in a way.
Inside me.
It's not the same.
And I think you'd agree with me.
They have families.
Friends.
People who love them
and miss them
and want them back,
just as I do.
But restoring their lives
means sacrificing mine.
Captain...
what you're considering
is an execution.
An execution--
like they used to do
to murderers centuries ago--
and I've committed
no crime at all.
Aren't you arguing
for an execution, too--
of Tuvok and Neelix?
I'm here-- alive.
Unfortunate as it may be,
they're gone.
And I have an opportunity
to bring them back.
Don't you think that I care
about Tuvok and Neelix?
Of course I do!
Without them,
I wouldn't exist.
In a way, I think of them
as my parents.
I feel like
I know them intimately.
Then you know Tuvok was a man
who would gladly give
his life to save another.
And I believe the same
was true of Neelix.
You're right, Captain.
That is the Starfleet way.
And I know there'll
be some people
who will call me a coward
because I didn't
sacrifice myself
willingly.
Believe me,
I've thought of that.
But I have the will to live
of two men.
Look at me, Captain.
When I'm happy, I laugh.
When I'm sad, I cry.
When I stub my toe,
I yell out in pain.
I'm flesh and blood.
And I... have the right
to live!
Kes...
I need your help.
I've just come
from the Captain,
and she's thinking
about forcing me
to go through
with the separation.
If anybody can make
a difference, Kes, it's you.
She'll listen to you.
We've helped each other
through this,
and I know that you care
about what happens to me.
Please.
Kes, you may be my only hope.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Captain...
Tuvix has asked me
to speak to you on his behalf.
But I can't.
He shouldn't have put you
in the middle of this.
But I am in the middle.
I have been since
the moment of the accident.
I don't know how to say good-bye
to Neelix and Tuvok.
I know this sounds horrible...
and I feel so guilty
for saying it...
and Tuvix doesn't
deserve to die...
but I want Neelix back.
( sobbing )
You're excused, Ensign.
Mr. Paris,
what is our present speed?
Warp 6.5.
I'd like to conduct a field test
of the aft sensor array.
Please, slow to impulse.
Commander?
Until the Captain
makes a decision,
Mr. Tuvix is still
the Tactical Officer.
Mr. Tuvix?
I'd like to speak
to you alone.
Can I assume that you've
come to a decision, Captain?
I have.
I think we all
should hear
what you have
to say!
Please come with
me, Mr. Tuvix.
No.
I'm ordering you
to come with me.
Security to the Bridge.
Commander, are you going
to stand by and do nothing
while she commits murder?!
Wha..?
Mr. Ayala!
Yes...
Lieutenant Paris...
you...
Doesn't anyone see
that this is wrong?!
( door opens )
( panting )
JANEWAY:
Let him go.
Each of you
is going to have
to live with this...
and I'm sorry for that.
For you are all good...
good people.
My colleagues.
My friends.
I forgive you.
Commander Chakotay,
advise the Doctor
we're on our way to Sick Bay.
Deck 5.
I'm sorry, Captain,
but I cannot perform
the surgical separation.
I am a physician,
and a physician
must do no harm.
I will not take
Mr. Tuvix' life
against his will.
Very well, Doctor.
Please step aside.
I assume this is
the radioisotope.
Please sit down
on this bio-bed.
Locking surgical
targeting scanners
onto the isotope probe.
Initiating
separation sequence.
Energizing.
Neelix!
Hello, sweeting!
Greetings,
Captain.
Mr. Tuvok...
Mr. Neelix...
it's good to have you back.