( birds chirping )
( equipment humming )
( gentle theme playing )
( beeping )
Sickbay to the Captain.
This is the doctor speaking.
You've brought us
out of stasis.
I assume you have news.
Yes.
Our sensors show
your vital signs are normal.
How are you feeling?
We're fine.
How long were we in stasis?
A total of 17 days.
JANEWAY:
That long?
I wanted to exhaust every
possibility of finding a cure.
And?
I regret to inform you
that I have been
unsuccessful.
I have not been able to develop
a counteragent for the virus,
and I have no other options
to explore.
What about keeping us
in stasis aboard Voyager?
Something
in the planet's environment
is shielding you
from the effects of the virus.
If you leave,
you risk a recurrence
of the disease,
which would undoubtedly
prove fatal.
The only option I can
think of at the moment
is contacting the Vidiians.
They have sophisticated
medical technology.
It's possible they
might be able to help.
We'll take it under
advisement, doctor.
Thank you for your efforts.
Janeway out.
What do you think?
It's risky.
The Vidiians
have never shown
any willingness
to help us.
It's more likely
they'd attack Voyager
and try to harvest body parts
from the crew.
Agreed.
I just want to make sure
we're not overlooking
a possible alternative.
Could we live
with ourselves,
knowing we'd sent Voyager
into that kind of danger?
Janeway to Tuvok.
I'm here, Captain.
You must be aware
of the doctor's report.
Yes.
I'm turning over command
of the ship to you
on a permanent basis.
Your orders are to resume a
course for the Alpha Quadrant.
And regardless of
the doctor's suggestion,
you are not to make contact
with the Vidiians.
I understand.
I'll prepare a message
for the crew.
( majestic theme playing )
So we're just going to
abandon them on this planet?
Those were Captain Janeway's
express orders.
But you're Captain now.
You can rescind them.
To what end?
I can't believe
we haven't been able
to find a cure
for an insect bite.
KES:
The doctor hasn't
deactivated himself
for a month.
He's tried everything.
He's searched every database,
attempted
the most drastic research.
You can't fault him.
I can tell you the morale
of the crew is going to suffer
if we leave them behind.
Not if, Mr. Neelix.
When we leave them behind.
The decision
has been made.
We will, of course,
provide them with
everything they'll need
for their survival and comfort.
I am arranging
for a modular shelter
to be transported
to the surface.
They'll have all the technology
they need--
weapons, tricorders,
a replicator.
You talk as though
it were a camping trip.
They have to spend the rest
of their lives down there.
That is not a certainty.
Captain Janeway intends to
continue researching the virus.
She is an able scientist,
and may eventually be able
to effect a cure.
They have a type-9 shuttlecraft
at their disposal,
if it becomes possible
for them to leave the planet.
A type-9 shuttlecraft has
a top speed of warp 4.
It won't take them more than...
oh, about 700 years to get home.
I am not certain what it is
you expect me to do, Lieutenant.
I guess, clearly,
something you can't do,
which is to feel as rotten
about this as we do.
You are correct that I am unable
to experience that emotion.
And frankly, I fail to see
what the benefit would be.
If there is nothing more,
you are all dismissed.
Janeway to Tuvok.
Yes, Captain?
We've received the transport.
We'll check it over and let you
know if we're missing anything.
I will remain in orbit
until I hear from you.
And, after that, we can still
remain in communication
for approximately 36 hours.
I'll contact you
before the day is over.
Janeway out.
It looks like
they transported
the contents of
the whole ship.
We may have to be here
for a while.
Petri dishes, protein analyzer,
DNA sequencers.
Everything I need for
my research is here.
Do you really think
you can find a cure?
It may take a while,
but, yes, I do.
If I can find a specimen of
the insect that infected us,
I can begin analyzing
protein cofactors.
That might give us
the information we need
to find out what it is
in this environment
that's keeping us
from being sick
and how to replicate it.
Does it matter
which way these things go?
I guess it depends
whether you're
in a beige mood
or a gray mood.
That's not much of a choice.
Couldn't Starfleet
have come up
with something
a little more cheerful?
Like polka dots?
I was thinking more
of a tasteful pinstripe,
something
in blues and greens.
Well, I suggest we put
the gray on the outside
and the beige inside.
I like that.
I've always looked
better in beige.
Actually, it might
be kind of interesting,
roughing it for a while.
"Roughing it"?
Let's see.
We have shelter, furniture,
research equipment,
tricorders, a replicator.
It's too rough for me.
We don't have a bathtub.
A bathtub?
I love a bath. It's
my favorite way of relaxing.
Captain, I'm sure you can learn
to love the sonic shower.
You know, Chakotay,
it occurs to me,
we aren't exactly in a
command structure anymore.
Maybe you should
call me Kathryn.
Give me a few days on that one,
okay?
This diagnostic report
looks like it was written
by a first-year Academy cadet.
There are mistakes.
It's incomplete.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
I guess I've
been distracted.
We've all been distracted,
Ensign.
That's no excuse.
Yes, ma'am.
I can't get
anything done here.
Nobody can concentrate.
I know how they feel.
I'm not feeling
so terrific myself,
but I don't let that
get in the way of my work.
B'Elanna...
I've been talking with some
of the Starfleet crew.
They're not happy
about what happened.
I was wondering...
how are the Maquis taking it?
How do you think
they're taking it?
This isn't
a Starfleet issue, Harry.
It's affecting everyone.
Then why don't we do
something about it?
Do what?
I don't know.
It seems like we shouldn't
just accept this.
Well, that's
all well and good,
but, frankly, I can't think
of anything else we can do.
If you have any ideas,
I'll listen.
Otherwise, I think we should
take a deep breath and move on.
( gentle theme playing )
Catch anything?
Just the same ones
as yesterday,
and they don't seem to carry
the pathogen
that's infected us.
Where have you been?
Oh, in the woods.
For the past two days,
you've been spending
a lot of time in the woods.
Is something going on
I should know about?
Uh, not yet.
Not yet?
What's that
supposed to mean?
It means, when it's time
for you to know, I'll tell you.
Don't I even
get hints?
I'm building something.
Building?
What could you be building?
And why can't you tell me?
You can't stand it, can you?
You're like a little kid,
wheedling.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Janeway here.
We're about to move
out of communications range.
How are you faring?
We're doing quite well.
I'd like to speak
to the crew now.
Your com link has been
put through to the entire ship.
This is Kathryn Janeway.
I've never liked
saying good-bye,
so I'll make this brief.
But I want you all to know
that serving as your Captain
has been the most extraordinary
experience of my life.
No Captain could ask more
than what this crew has given--
bravery, compassion
and strength of character.
But I think what I'll miss most
is the fun.
The times we joked together,
the games on the holodeck.
I'll remember the laughter
more than anything.
Although Commander Chakotay
and I won't be with you
for the rest of your journey,
we know that you'll be the same
steadfast crew for Mr. Tuvok
as you have been for us.
We wish you a safe
and a speedy journey home.
Our thoughts will be with you.
Janeway out.
TUVOK:
Thank you, Captain, Commander.
I am sure I speak
for the entire crew when I say
we will always remember
your grace and courage.
And I would like to add,
it has been an honor
serving with you.
Live long and prosper.
( gentle theme playing )
Kathryn Janeway's Personal Log,
Stardate 49690.1.
Day 24 of our stay on the
planet we've named New Earth.
As yet, I've been unable
to make any progress
in finding
a cure for our illness,
but a soak
in the tub Chakotay built
always helps me focus
on possible solutions.
Chakotay, are you there?
CHAKOTAY:
No, I left an hour ago.
I was thinking.
Maybe looking
for protein cofactors
is the wrong approach.
Even if I can't find
a specimen of the insect
that infected us...
I could try to learn something
about the biomolecular evolution
of this planet's ecosystem.
Can't hurt to give it a try.
( rustling )
( gasps )
Chakotay!
What?
Someone's in the woods.
( suspenseful theme playing )
(whispering ):
Over there.
( chittering )
It looks like
some kind of primate.
I've detected primate
life-signs here,
but I've never seen one.
Hello.
Are you hungry?
Is that why you came here?
I'm Kathryn.
He's Chakotay.
We've had to move
into your neighborhood,
but I hope we can be friends.
( chittering )
Oh. Maybe he'll come back.
Looking for a pet?
No. Looking for a clue
about primate physiology
on this planet.
They must have to contend
with insect bites, too.
Well...excuse me.
Maybe we should be
out looking
for other primates.
I might be missing
something important.
Kathryn...
the doctor worked
for weeks
trying to find a treatment
for this disease.
Yes.
You've been at it
12 hours a day,
seven days a week
since we got here,
and we're still
no closer to a cure
than we were the day
we were infected.
I'm not sure
what you're getting at.
( sighing )
My people have a saying.
"Even the eagle
must know when to sleep."
Maybe it's time
we both considered that.
You mean quit. Give up.
Why do you have
to see it as defeat?
Maybe it's simply...
accepting what life
has dealt us,
finding the good in it.
( sighs )
There may be a day when I'll
come to that, Chakotay, but...
I'm a long way
from it right now.
I need to keep looking.
( gentle theme playing )
TUVOK:
Acting Captain's Log,
supplemental.
After six weeks, the decision
to leave Captain Janeway
and the First Officer behind
still seems to weigh heavily
on the crew.
( console beeping )
Captain Tuvok?
Yes, Ensign?
I'm picking up a convoy
on long-range sensors.
It's Vidiian, sir.
Distance?
Approximately 1.5 light-years.
Lieutenant, alter course
to a different heading.
I don't want to risk
their detecting us.
Sir, the Vidiians...
Yes?
They're within hailing range.
We could ask them
if they know anything
about the Captain's illness.
You're aware
that Captain Janeway
specifically told us not
to risk contacting the Vidiians?
Yes, but it's not like we went
out of our way to find them.
We would just be
taking advantage
of an opportunity
that's presented itself.
That bit of sophistry is not
terribly persuasive, Ensign.
Sir, how can we
turn our backs
on this chance
to do something?
Don't we have to try?
Don't we owe that
to the Captain
and the Commander?
The matter
is closed, Ensign.
Return to your station.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What's wrong
with the rest of you?
You know I'm right.
Ensign Kim.
We have a chance
to help them.
How can we ignore that?
Ensign, you are
relieved of duty.
Leave the Bridge at once,
or I will have you
put in the brig.
Harry...
Proceed on the altered course,
Lieutenant.
Excuse me, Ensign Kim.
Could we?
Sure. Have a seat.
We just wanted
you to know,
we heard what happened
on the Bridge.
And we think
you're absolutely right.
We've got to contact
the Vidiians.
It's a risk,
but it's worth it.
That's what I think,
but Captain Tuvok's
made his decision.
Two Ensigns and a crewman
won't change his mind.
There are a lot more
who agree with us.
A lot.
Really?
Everyone we talk to
can't believe
that Tuvok won't
give this a try.
Come on.
Did you hear what happened
this morning?
Sure did.
Three weeks ago,
you said if I had an idea
about what to do,
you'd listen.
I'm listening.
Is there something going on
that I should know about?
Have a seat, Neelix.
We might have come up
with the biggest
morale booster
you could
possibly imagine.
( soft theme playing )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Could I have
a moment, sir?
It's 0100 hours, Ensign.
Don't you have
the early shift this morning?
Yes, sir, but this is important.
Very well.
First of all,
I want to apologize
for my behavior
yesterday.
Apology accepted.
I understand that this is
a difficult situation for you.
I'd like to suggest a plan.
It's something a lot of people
have helped to develop.
We have
two big bargaining points
when it comes to dealing
with the Vidiians.
First, there's the woman
doc treated-- Danara Pel.
They were very close,
so I'm sure she'd help us
if she could.
And then there's B'Elanna.
Her DNA might lead to a cure
for the phage.
We could offer them some--
in exchange for their help
with a cure
for the Captain and Chakotay.
Those are, as you say,
points in our favor,
but there is also the fact
that we
were recently responsible
for the destruction
of a Vidiian ship,
an act which killed over 300
of their people.
That alone makes it unwise
for us to contact them.
Sir...
I think you should know
how many people on this ship
disagree with you.
Everyone I talked to thinks
we should give this a try.
The people you talked to
do not have the responsibility
of commanding this vessel.
I do.
The safety of this crew
is paramount,
and I must do whatever I can
to ensure that safety.
But if we're willing
to take that risk in order
to help
the Captain...
Ensign, I'm going
to say this once
and once only.
If you ever question
my orders again,
you will be relieved
of duty permanently.
The next words
I expect to hear from you
are, "yes, sir."
Yes...
sir.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( door opens, closes )
I'm going to check the
insect traps in beta-4.
Oh, what are you
up to now?
Making headboards.
Headboards?
I've noticed you sometimes
sit up in your bed to read.
Figured you might as well
have a comfortable backrest.
That's very thoughtful
of you, Chakotay.
You've done so many things
to make our lives
easier here.
The cooking, for example.
I hate to cook.
But what I do makes you
uncomfortable, doesn't it?
Every time
I do something
that adds
a personal touch
to the shelter,
you resist it.
Sometimes it feels...
as though you've given up.
That you're focused
on making a home here
instead of finding a cure
that will let us leave.
I can't sacrifice
the present
waiting for a future
that may never happen.
The reality
of this situation
is that we may never
leave here.
So, yes, I'm trying
to make a home--
something that's more
than a plain gray box.
Someday I may have to let go.
But not today, okay?
I tried a new glucose
bait in the traps.
I have a feeling
this might be the day
I make a breakthrough.
( tool rasping )
( rustling )
Hello?
Chakotay?
( chittering )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hello again.
( chittering )
Well, you certainly
cover a lot of territory.
Or are you
following me?
Do you understand me?
( calls )
There.
Know what that is?
That little insect
just might be
what gets me out
of your backyard.
What do you think of that, huh?
( agitated cries )
What is it?
What's happened to the sky?
If you're suggesting I should
get out of here, I agree.
( wind howling )
( agitated cries continue )
( thunder cracks )
Oh!
Kathryn!
Kathryn.
Are you hurt?
No. I couldn't
keep my balance
and carry the case.
Give it to me.
What's happening?
It seems to be some
kind of plasma storm.
Our tricorders
don't recognize it,
but it sure packs a wallop.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Do you have a moment?
Of course.
Please sit down.
I'd like to talk to you...
about my father.
Your father?
He was a very wise man.
More than anyone,
he shaped the person I am.
If it hadn't been for him,
I would have never questioned
my people's beliefs.
I would have never
left our city.
I would never have met
all of you.
Then we owe him a debt.
It is difficult to imagine
this journey without you.
When he died,
I had just turned one year old.
I didn't know
how I'd get through
the rest of my life
without him,
but then I started
working with you
and I didn't miss him
so much anymore.
I am honored by the comparison.
As Captain,
the well-being of your crew
is important to you.
Of course.
Their emotional well-being
as well as
their physical safety?
I cannot allow myself to become
hostage to their feelings.
Tuvok, they are suffering
because of this.
Maybe you don't know
what it's like.
If you are
suggesting
that I am not sensitive
to the situation,
nothing could be further
from the truth.
I have lost a valued friend.
I am not immune to the effects
of that loss.
Then try to imagine
what it's like
for those of us
who feel things deeply.
A lot of the crew
are on the Bridge,
hoping you'll talk to them.
( slow theme playing )
( murmured conversations )
None of you can
appreciate
what it means to be
in command of a ship
until that responsibility
rests squarely on your shoulders
as it does on mine.
It has been suggested
that I take an action,
which would require me
to disobey an order,
and knowingly put this crew into
a life-threatening situation.
In general, I believe it
demonstrates faulty leadership
to be guided by the emotions
of a distraught crew.
However, as Captain,
I must not ignore
the sensibilities
of those I command.
We will contact the Vidiians.
This is my decision
and mine alone.
You are all absolved
of responsibility in the matter.
I will accept any consequences
which may ensue.
Lieutenant, set a course
for the Vidiian convoy.
Mr. Kim, let me know when we're
within hailing range.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Oh! Oh, no!
CHAKOTAY:
Let's check outside.
Maybe some of the insect traps
are still intact.
( sighs )
None of this
is salvageable either.
There's no way I can
continue to do my research.
I'm sorry.
Well, that's one way
of letting go.
TUVOK:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 49694.2.
We have contacted
the Vidiian convoy
with encouraging results.
They have promised
to communicate
with Dr. Danara Pel
and ask if she will help us.
Sir, the Vidiians
are hailing us.
On screen.
PEL:
Hello, Lieutenant.
Doctor Pel,
I didn't expect
to see you this quickly.
When I heard what happened, I
boarded the first ship I could.
Tell me about this illness.
They were infected
by a virus
after being bitten by insects
on a planet approximately
70 light-years from here
in a system
with a yellow dwarf star.
The third planet
in a system of seven?
Yes.
I know it well.
There's a particular kind
of burrowing insect
that carries the disease.
Years ago, we developed an
antiviral agent to combat it.
Can we get some from you?
Of course. Our Captain said
we could rendezvous with you.
He's transmitted
the coordinates.
( console beeps )
I have them, sir.
Thank you, doctor.
We appreciate your help.
I'm glad I can
be of assistance.
Estimated time
to the coordinates?
Approximately 20 hours.
Until then, I want
a series of battle drills.
We must be ready
for whatever comes.
I've been thinking...
there's plenty of wood
available here.
I could probably add
rooms to the shelter.
Give us a little more
living space.
How would you mill it?
I could do a certain
amount with a phaser,
but I was actually
thinking of logs.
As in log cabin?
I built a few of them
when I was growing up.
My father thought
it was important
that I learn how.
When I was young, my parents
took us on backpacking trips.
They thought we should all
keep a connection
to our pioneer roots.
I hated it--
no bed, no replicator...
No bathtub.
I guess I was always a child
of the 24th century.
Well...
maybe those camping trips
helped prepare you
for life here.
Oh, no.
Life here is much better
than that.
I think that's the first time
I've heard you say anything
positive about being here.
( chittering )
Well, hello there.
I haven't seen you
in a while.
Where have you been?
Do you expect him
to answer you?
( whispers ):
Not really. I just sense
intelligence in him,
and I could swear
he came to warn me
about the plasma storm.
Come here, fella.
Come on.
I doubt that he
can be domesticated--
at least not very easily.
( chittering )
Well, we have
plenty of time.
The rest of our lives.
( sighs )
That's a long time.
At least I hope so.
( laughs )
Well, I can't give you
orders anymore,
but I suggest we get
back to work.
Aye, aye, Captain.
( gentle theme playing )
( groans softly )
I guess I'm not used
to that kind of work.
( chuckling )
My knots are getting knots.
Here, let me help.
Oh, that feels good.
I've had a lot
of practice at this.
My mother used to get
sore necks all the time.
I was the only one she'd trust
not to make it worse.
That's much better.
Thank you.
Well...I'm going
to go to bed now.
I'll see you in the morning.
Sleep well, Kathryn.
Yes.
You, too.
( sighs )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( console beeps )
Got something.
Vidiian ship,
bearing 325 mark 5.
Hail them.
They aren't responding.
Trying
on alternating frequencies.
I'm reading a second ship,
177 mark 5.
I've got it.
Now a third.
They're surrounding us.
None of them are answering hails
and their weapons are powered.
Red Alert.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( blows )
We have to talk
about this.
All right.
I think we need to define
some parameters...
about us.
I'm not sure I can...
define parameters.
But I can tell you a story--
an ancient legend
among my people.
It's about an angry warrior
who lived his life
in conflict with the
rest of his tribe--
a man who couldn't
find peace,
even with the help
of his spirit guide.
For years, he struggled
with his discontent.
But the only satisfaction
he ever got
came when he was in battle.
This made him a hero
among his tribe,
but the warrior still longed
for peace within himself.
One day, he and his war party
were captured
by a neighboring tribe
led by a woman warrior.
She called on him to join her
because her tribe was too small
and weak to defend itself
from all its enemies.
The woman warrior
was brave and beautiful
and very wise.
The angry warrior
swore to himself...
that he would stay by her side,
doing whatever he could
to make her burden lighter.
From that point on,
her needs would come first.
And in that way...
the warrior began to know...
the true meaning of peace.
Is that really...
an ancient legend?
No.
But that made it easier to say.
( gentle theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Shields down to 58 percent.
Rearm the forward phaser
array and fire at will.
Firing.
Shields down to 47 percent.
Sir, there are just
too many of them.
Load aft torpedo bays.
Torpedoes armed.
TUVOK:
Fire number one.
Report.
They're still coming.
Fire number two.
Tuvok to Engineering.
Torres here, sir.
Listen carefully.
( both grunt )
( moaning )
She has
a broken arm.
Set it with the osteogenic
stimulator.
I think there's someone
on the monitor.
This way.
Odd. Why wouldn't they
just use the com line?
I don't think this is coming
from our ship.
DANARA:
Shmullus...
Shmullus, can you hear me?
Danara.
Shmullus,
I have to do this quickly.
I'm on one
of the Vidiian ships.
( grunts )
Do they know
you're contacting me?
Are you in any danger?
No. Everyone's too focused
on the battle.
Oh, Shmullus, I swear I didn't
know they planned to attack.
I thought we were on
an errand of mercy.
I believe you.
I have the antiviral serum
here. If you could use
your transporter
to get it to your...
Our shields are up.
We can't transport anything
through them.
I don't know what else
to suggest.
All right.
I'll see what I can do.
Maybe we can
lower the shields
long enough
to transport the serum.
Sickbay to Bridge.
This is Tuvok.
We're rather busy
here, doctor.
Doctor Pel is on
one of the Vidiian ships.
If we can drop
our shields briefly,
we can beam aboard the serum.
Keep this com
line open, doctor.
When you hear me
order the shields down,
you must complete a site-to-site
transport yourself.
We will be busy
with the Vidiians.
Understood.
Bridge to Engineering.
Report.
We're ready to eject
the antimatter container.
Stand by for my command.
Here is the sequence of events.
We will drop shields
to transport the medicine.
At the same moment,
the antimatter container
will be ejected.
As soon as it's clear,
Mr. Kim will detonate it
with a photon torpedo.
Simultaneously, Mr. Paris
will jump to full impulse,
so that we will not take
the brunt of the explosion.
Is everyone clear on this?
Timing is
of the utmost importance.
We won't get a second chance.
Understood.
Aye, sir.
We're ready down here.
Doctor?
I've set up
to make the transport.
Stand ready, then.
( dramatic theme playing )
Lower shields.
Initiating transport.
Ejecting
the antimatter container...
now.
We've got it.
Raise shields.
Mr. Kim, Mr. Paris?
Go.
Firing torpedo.
Report.
The Vidiian ships
are all disabled, sir.
They're not pursuing.
Ready to go
to warp, sir.
Set a course for the planet
where we left the Captain
and Commander Chakotay.
Warp 6.
Aye, aye, sir.
How are they coming?
Very nicely.
We should have vine-ripened
Talaxian tomatoes
in a couple of months...
unless this planet has
the equivalent of tomato bugs.
Oh, they're awful.
I would never
have thought
of you
as a gardener.
Hmm. I grew up around farmers.
My parents insisted we learn
some basic gardening skills.
Did you hate that
as much as camping?
Of course.
Who wanted to muck around
in the dirt
when you could be studying
quantum mechanics?
( chuckles )
But...I find it
very satisfying now,
watching the seeds sprout
and grow.
If your tomatoes
could spare you for a minute,
I'd like your opinion
on something
in the house.
You've come
to the right person.
I always have an opinion.
Really?
( laughs )
What do you think?
A boat.
You said you wanted
to explore the river?
I think I could
build this.
We could go on
a camping trip.
I'm not sure we could fit
the bathtub in the boat.
Well, that's all right.
I'll have the river.
( muffled com noise )
Do you hear that?
Yes.
TUVOK ( staticky ):
...to Captain Janeway.
Do you read me?
This is Tuvok calling Captain
Janeway and Commander Chakotay.
Please respond.
This is Janeway.
Captain, it's good
to hear your voice.
We have news.
What is it?
We have medicine
which we believe
will effectively treat
your condition.
We plan to be in orbit
within 30 hours.
( melancholy theme playing )
Ready?
( chittering )
JANEWAY:
There you are.
At least I get to say good-bye.
Feel free to use
the house.
( chittering )
Janeway to Voyager.
Two to beam up.
( chittering )
( slow theme playing )
Welcome back,
Captain.
Commander.
The doctor tells me
you contacted the Vidiians
after all.
I disobeyed your
order, Captain.
I am prepared to accept
the consequences.
If I didn't know
you better,
I'd say your decision
was almost...emotional.
Thank you all.
Well, we've lost time
with all this.
Let's see if we can make
some of it up.
Mr. Paris, warp 8.
Aye, Captain.
Commander, we'll need
to review the ship's systems.
I'll handle propulsion,
environmental and communication.
You'll handle sensors,
weapons and transporters.
Aye, Captain.
I'll have a report to you
by 1800 hours.
Check with phaser maintenance.
See if they solved that problem
with the prefire
chamber temperature.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll see to it.
( majestic theme playing )