Look.
And you said they were
incompatible.
TUVOK:
You have confirmed
the genetic structure?
An entirely new species.
I'm gonna name it after you.
The Tuvok orchid.
That is an honor you should
reserve for yourself, Mr. Suder.
You gave this species life.
And you gave me life.
All of this is because of you.
Because of the meld.
The meld may have
introduced you
to my interest
in floriculture,
but you have embraced it
entirely on your own.
And discovered a unique
talent within yourself
in the process.
I used to think
the only talent I had
was a talent for killing.
Please... It's my way
of saying thank you.
Very well.
I accept.
Tuvok, I want to do
something for the ship.
I'm not asking you
to let me out of confinement.
I accept my punishment.
But if I could just...
Just contribute somehow.
What contribution do you
feel you could make
from your quarters?
I was... I was thinking
I might adapt
some of the genetic
engineering techniques
I've developed for the orchids
to make the airponic vegetable
garden more productive.
Your attitude is admirable.
I will discuss it with
the Captain.
Do you think she'll agree?
We'll see.
Now, shall we begin?
Notice your mind working.
How it plans for the future,
visits the past.
Notice those thoughts
and set them aside.
Turn your attention
to the white light
that is your breath.
Captain, we're being hailed
on a subspace frequency.
Are there ships
in the vicinity?
Negative.
Tracking the source.
Seems likes it's coming
from an unmanned buoy.
Coordinates 140 mark 317.
It looks like a Kazon signal,
Captain.
Take us out of warp.
Open a channel.
SESKA:
Chakotay, they're going
to take your son.
When Culluh saw the baby...
I hear them coming.
I don't have much time.
When he saw
the baby wasn't his...
Please, Chakotay, help us--
Not for me, for your son.
CULLUH:
I told you to stay out of here.
SESKA:
No, please don't.
Don't take him!
I beg... No! Please, no!
No!
( dramatic theme playing )
( triumphant theme playing )
This is not
my responsibility.
She has no right
to expect me--
She knows you, Chakotay.
She knew how you'd react
when you saw your son in danger.
I have a duty to this crew.
I can't just leave
and go looking for the child.
And I'd never consider
letting you go
into a Kazon-Nistrim
stronghold by yourself.
If we do this,
we do it together.
That's something else
Seska would know too.
Do you think it's a trap?
Do I think Seska
is capable
of manipulating
you and me with this?
Oh, yes.
On the other hand,
it was time
for her to deliver.
And that baby we saw
did look part Cardassian
and part human.
And knowing Culluh,
I'm sure his pride was wounded
when he realized
the child wasn't his.
It makes sense, Chakotay.
It might all be true.
Still, the safest
thing would be
to ignore this message
and resume our course.
I'm not going to resume
our course just yet.
I want you to think
about it, Chakotay.
This has to be your decision.
If you choose to go after him,
I know I speak
for the entire crew--
Starfleet and Maquis alike--
When I say
we'll stand behind you.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeps )
Ah-koo-chee-moya.
We are far from the sacred
places of our grandfathers.
We are far from the bones
of my people,
but I ask on this day
of sorrow and uncertainty
that the wisdom
of my father find me
and help me understand
my dilemma.
Speak to me, Father.
Speak to me in my dreams.
KOLOPAK:
I've never seen you
so troubled, Chakotay.
I have a son, Father.
A son, Chakotay?
Oh.
This is the reason
for your despair.
Was he born with two arms
and two legs
and a heart that beats?
Yes, but--
Then it's a cause
for celebration.
You will make a fine father.
You needn't worry.
I'm not sure I'm willing
to be a father to him.
Hmm. Not willing?
He was born
without my consent.
I had no part in it.
No part in it?
Well, it's been a long time,
so forgive me,
but it seems that I
had to play a part
before your mother
could conceive.
My DNA was taken from me.
Used by a woman
to impregnate herself
without my permission.
I see.
You're trying to decide
whether you should
accept the child
in your heart.
It's more than that.
But it must begin with that!
How do you take
a child into your heart
who is forced upon you
by a mother's deception?
He knows nothing
of deception.
He is innocent.
Centuries ago, when
the women of our tribe
were raped by
white conquerors,
many gave birth
to their children.
And we did not reject them.
They were accepted
by the tribe.
One was a direct ancestor
of ours, Chakotay.
His name was Ce Acatl.
He became a great leader
of our people.
Here is a man
who was given life
without
his mother's consent.
Are you so different
from her?
And is your child
so different from Ce Acatl?
No.
He is your son, Chakotay.
And he is a child
of our people.
( dramatic theme playing )
I've been in touch
with the Talaxian
mining colony on Prema II.
They're willing to come
to our assistance
if we run into trouble.
That's good for about 40 hours
if we average warp 2.
After that, we're out
of their com range.
Well, it's nice to know
we have friends in the area.
Thank you, Neelix.
I recommend a full diagnostic
of our tactical array
prior to the start
of the mission, Captain.
Agreed, but I want more
from tactical, Lieutenant.
I want to anticipate
a trap.
And I want a few tricks up
our sleeves, if we need them.
Captain, I could program the
deflector grid to make it look
like we have help
on the way.
I'll show you
what I mean.
Excuse me, doctor.
( beeps )
Echo displacement.
KIM:
Exactly.
This is how we'd look
to the enemy sensors.
If we generate multiple
decoy images like these,
the Kazon would think that
ships are coming toward us.
We could create
as many as we want.
That's a good start, Harry.
It should distract them
for a while.
But what else can we do
if we're eventually intercepted
by a superior force?
DOCTOR:
If you don't mind,
I do have something to add.
( beeps )
Thank you.
Captain, I hesitate
to offer suggestions
in a field of endeavor
that is not
within my usual area
of expertise.
Please, doctor,
your suggestions
on any subject
are always welcome.
Really? In that case,
you may expect several more
on a variety of matters
in the near future.
Right now, may I suggest
that we also consider
attempting to create
an actual holographic illusion
of friendly ships.
With all due respect, doctor,
we can't even figure out how
to project you into this room.
How are we supposed to create
holographic ships in space?
DOCTOR:
I would humbly submit
that my program
is far more sophisticated
than your run-of-the-mill
hologram.
In fact, projecting
the illusion
of a large
three-dimensional object
has been a trick of magicians
for centuries.
We'll just do it
with mirrors.
DOCTOR:
Mr. Paris' predictable attempts
at humor not withstanding,
that is precisely
what I would suggest.
Installing holo-emitters along
the hull with parabolic mirrors
to enlarge the images as they
are reflected into space.
We're gonna use up
a lot of our power reserves
trying to pull it off.
CHAKOTAY:
If these ships
can fool the Kazon,
it's worth it.
TUVOK:
But can they? If the Kazon
scan the holograms,
they will immediately realize
there are no life signs
on board,
no power signatures...
Okay, so we can't
fool them for long,
but maybe it'll be
long enough.
It's an advantage.
And we'll need every advantage
we can get on this mission.
Work on the doctor with it,
B'Elanna.
Mr. Kim, cut power
to all systems
to minimum requirements.
I don't wanna show up
on any Kazon
long-range scanners.
Mr. Paris, locate the warp
signature from Culluh's ship
and set a course
to follow, warp 2.
Aye, Captain.
Dismissed.
CHAKOTAY:
Uh, excuse me,
but there is one more thing.
Thank you.
( dramatic theme playing )
It's not Culluh's ship.
Looks more like a shuttle.
Slow to impulse.
Set an intercept course,
Mr. Paris.
Have they indicated
the nature of the distress?
Just a signal, Captain.
No response to our hails.
Let's go to red alert.
( alarm sounds )
Visual range.
On screen.
KIM:
Showing one life sign.
Adult Kazon male.
He's in critical condition.
Janeway to Sickbay.
Prepare to receive
an emergency transport.
KES: Standing by, Captain.
Commander.
Mr. Tuvok, you have the Bridge.
Remain at red alert.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
KES:
His hip is broken.
Showing severe inflammation
in the bronchial tissue.
It appears he inhaled
noxious gases
vented in
the damaged shuttle.
40 milligrams
pulmozine.
CHAKOTAY:
I know this man.
His name's Tierna.
He's one of Seska's aides.
She had him work me over
when I was on their ship.
( grunting ):
Seska...is dead.
( dramatic theme playing )
TIERNA:
Seska thought that she
could manipulate the maje.
She bragged about it to me
more than once,
but this time she was wrong.
We had just launched the buoy
with the message for you.
Then they came for her.
They cut her throat,
as Culluh watched.
He ordered them to execute me,
but I bribed one of the guards
to get me to a shuttle.
As soon as he saw it leaving,
Culluh opened fire--
Destroyed
my life-support systems.
He left me in space
to die.
What about the child?
Taken to the Gema IV colony
to be raised as a servant.
We'll be needing your help
getting to the Gema system.
You're going after him?
This ship, alone?
I want nothing to do with this.
I'm not taking you
into Nistrim space.
Under the circumstances, I'd say
you don't have much of a choice.
What's his prognosis?
He'll be on his feet
in a day or two,
but there's still
a number of things
we need to keep an eye on.
He's had...a nasty concussion,
spinal cord trauma
and a polycythemia, the cause
of which I've yet to discover.
Polycythemia?
An abnormal increase in
the number of red blood cells.
I'd like you to run
an autonomic response analysis
the next time I question him.
I'm afraid
that won't help you determine
if he's telling the truth,
Commander.
An ARA depends on making
a baseline comparison
with a known response
for a given species.
Any Tom, Dick or Harry
from the Alpha Quadrant,
I could probably help you,
but not with any of the new
species of the Delta Quadrant.
( computer beeping )
Regarding his veracity,
it may help you to know
that if we'd arrived
an hour later,
he would have been dead
from his injuries.
The molecular variance residual
on his shuttle
is evidence of disruptor blasts,
and the signature is Kazon,
so at least that part of
his story seems to be true.
Plus, we confirmed
nitrogen tetroxide fumes
were in the cabin.
If all this was part of
a Kazon scheme,
he had to be willing
to breathe poison
for hours before
we got there.
Have you found
anything at all
that would cast
doubt on his story?
No.
I still don't trust him.
The trip would take six days
at warp 2.
NEELIX:
Four days, if you didn't take
such a circuitous route--
If we simply went
across the Tenarus cluster.
You would encounter
the Nistrim fleet
before a single day
passed.
Anyone who knows
this part of space
will tell you
the same thing.
NEELIX:
It so happens
that I do know
this part of space,
my Kazon friend.
I just wanted to see
if you would tell us the truth.
The route he suggests
is safer, Captain.
TIERNA:
Of course it's safer.
I don't want to run into Culluh
any more than you do.
CHAKOTAY:
We might have more
success avoiding him
if you gave us
the command codes
for the Nistrim
defense net.
TUVOK: Computer, display...
( computer beeping )
...tactical overview
of our current course.
Enter code sequence:
4-9-1-1-7-0-Culluh.
Mr. Paris, adjust our course
to avoid the defense net.
Aye, Captain.
TIERNA:
That is not an end
to the danger.
We are heading
into an area of space
populated
by Kazon factions
that are loyal to no one.
They will attack
without provocation.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Vessel approaching.
Coordinates: 314 mark 21.
Signature is
Kazon.
Red alert.
Configuration of the ship,
Mr. Tuvok?
A small raider,
Captain.
It does not pose
a significant threat.
Nevertheless, it is
powering up
its weapon systems.
( weapon fires in distance )
Shields are holding.
Return fire.
The raider is breaking
off its attack.
KIM:
Minor damage
to secondary command
processors on Deck 12.
EPS power supplies,
and isolinear controllers
are off-line.
No casualties though.
Begin repairs, Mr. Kim.
Any other sign of Kazon ships,
Lieutenant?
Nothing on
long-range sensors.
The raider is
continuing to retreat.
We should have
a couple of hours
to ourselves at least.
Good. We can use them.
Stand down red alert.
PARIS:
Captain,
we're about to go
beyond the com range
of the Talaxian colony.
Just thought
you'd like to know.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Maintain current course.
Captain.
I haven't forgotten,
Mr. Tuvok.
Very well.
This seems as good
a time as any.
( equipment beeping )
Captain.
Mr. Suder.
Please... P-please come in.
W-won't you sit down?
Excuse the mess.
I wasn't expecting company.
Can I get you some tea?
Have you had lunch?
Nothing, thank you.
Lieutenant Tuvok has been
telling me about your progress.
Has he? Well, I'm...
I'm very grateful to him,
Captain.
I still have a lot to learn,
of course,
but he is an excellent tutor.
When we first started
our studies, I--
TUVOK:
The Captain's time
is limited,
Mr. Suder.
What?
Oh.
Of course.
TUVOK:
I have explained
your proposal to her.
I'd like to know
more about it, Mr. Suder.
What exactly
would be involved?
Yes, yes...
Let me show you.
I've actually had
very encouraging results
with a new
gene-splicing technique.
I created a targeted
restriction enzyme
to facilitate
the hybrid.
And you feel
you could experiment
on our airponic crops
here in your quarters?
Absolutely. I would make this
an airponic laboratory,
and all I would need
are a few plants,
certain chemicals
and equipment.
What sort of chemicals
and equipment?
Nothing dangerous.
I-I've prepared a list.
It's an interesting
proposition, Mr. Suder.
Let me discuss it with Kes
and Lieutenant Tuvok,
and I'll get back to you.
I've already discussed it
with Kes,
and she is very interested.
Good. Let me give it
some thought.
If you're worried
you can't trust me, Captain--
Mr. Tuvok has assured--
I only want
to do something--
Something for the ship.
I understand, Mr. Suder.
Then what's the problem?
Why won't you give me
an answer?
Mr. Suder.
I just want to do
something for the ship.
Excuse me.
( dramatic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
None of the four Kazon attacks
have caused serious damage,
but the starboard ventral
has been hit each time--
complicating repairs on the
secondary command processors.
You are making an adequate
recovery, Mr. Tierna.
The only matter
that I simply cannot understand
is this lingering
polycythemia.
I feel fine.
The medical record
you gave us
does not indicate
any prior blood disorders.
Might it be
an inherited trait?
Do you know if
your parents ever--?
My parents were killed
in a Trabe attack
shortly after I was born.
I see. Well,
we'll need to monitor
this condition for a while.
It might be due to some
chemical imbalance
that our sensors
aren't recognizing.
Possibly the result
of the toxins you inhaled
while on the shuttle.
You're welcome.
Feeling better?
I'm sure I'll make
a complete recovery.
Just in time for the Gema
colony's defense force
to destroy us all.
You're still not optimistic
about our chances, are you?
No.
We've had no problem
repelling the attacks
so far.
Attacks... When there's
a real Nistrim attack,
you'll know it.
You still have pride in
the Nistrim, don't you, Tierna?
Even after
what they did to you.
I remember that pride
in your eyes when you
pounded me with your fists
while I was tied to a chair.
And I can see it
in your eyes now,
and that scares
the hell out of me.
You must scare easily,
Federation.
( grunts )
Tell me something,
Tierna.
Every Kazon attack seems to
focus on our starboard ventral.
Think that might be
some kind of pattern?
I wouldn't know.
Because if it is,
and you've been lying to us--
Commander
Chakotay.
Not in my Sickbay,
please.
( alarm sounding )
( dramatic theme playing )
( rumbling )
Firing phasers.
Increase speed
to one-half impulse.
Aye, Captain.
KIM: They're coming
at our starboard ventral
again.
Our shields there
haven't been repaired yet.
We're gonna sustain
more damage
to the secondary
command processors.
Starboard ventral.
COMPUTER: Warning.
Fires have been detected
on Decks 12 and 15
Sections A-4 through C-18.
Control units
are responding, Captain.
Keep our port forequarter facing
the line of attack, Mr. Paris.
Don't let them see
our starboard ventral.
I'm doing my best.
Continuous fire,
starboard phasers.
Acknowledged.
( rumbling continues )
TUVOK:
They're withdrawing,
Captain.
Stand down red alert.
Mr. Kim?
Deck 12 is in shambles.
We barely have time
to begin repairs
before they attack it again.
At least
no one was hurt.
The secondary
command processors
are nonfunctional.
We'll have
to rebuild them.
I'd say we're looking
at two days' work
if we're not
attacked again.
Why would these factions
of Kazon, loyal to no one,
all have the same agenda?
And why would that agenda
focus on a nonessential
area of the ship?
I don't know,
but it feels like
we're being pecked
to death by ducks.
We can't just stay on this
course and wait to see
what they have in store
for us.
I agree. It's time
to reexamine our game plan.
Mr. Paris, reverse course.
Aye, Captain.
CHAKOTAY:
Mr. Tierna should be
restricted to quarters
on a secured deck
until further notice.
Acknowledged.
( door beeps, opens )
( beeps )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Dinnertime, Mr. Suder.
We have
a fine leola root soup tonight.
I'm not hungry.
( alarm sounds )
Red alert.
I'm afraid we have to go.
I'll leave it here,
ah...
just in case.
( door closes )
How many do you count,
Mr. Tuvok?
Eight large carrier vessels,
confirmed Kazon signatures.
Funny how they show up
right after we reverse course.
Time to intercept?
Eight minutes.
Their attack formation is
a classic Cardassian echelon.
TUVOK:
Curious.
They have left us
with an obvious avenue
of escape, Captain.
You're right.
It is curious.
Too curious for me.
I don't know what's down
that avenue of escape,
Mr. Tuvok, but I like
to choose my own way.
Set a course
to intercept
their lead ship.
Aye, Captain.
Battle stations.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Time to intercept?
Three minutes,
10 seconds...
give or take
a photon torpedo.
Mr. Kim?
( console beeping )
Echo displacement ready,
Captain.
Send in the cavalry.
Activating deflector grid.
They should be seeing the same
thing on their scanners--
Ten ships
with Talaxian signatures.
Four of the Kazon ships
are breaking formation.
Confirmed.
They're changing course.
They took the bait.
That only leaves four
for us to handle.
I like those odds better
than eight to one.
Two minutes to intercept.
Janeway to Torres.
We're ready
down here, Captain.
All the new holo-projectors
are online.
We can create three Talaxian
ships whenever you want to.
JANEWAY:
In about a minute and a half,
B'Elanna. Stand by.
Perhaps we should try
one last systems check.
We've already done it twice.
DOCTOR:
I'm new at this,
and we've never put
such a demand on
the holo-generators before.
We should've boosted
the power input.
The defense systems are going
to need all the auxiliary power
we have, doctor.
We might try a preliminary--
Doctor!
It'll work.
Everything'll be fine.
I'm not worried.
( rumbling )
Here we go.
They are randomly detonating
torpedoes in our flight path.
Shields are holding.
No damage.
Hold your fire, Mr. Tuvok.
They may have torpedoes
to waste-- We don't.
Thirty seconds
to intercept.
Take us out of warp.
PARIS:
Engaging
impulse engines.
Power
to all weapon systems.
Stand by phasers.
TUVOK: Kazon vessel,
10,000 kilometers
off our starboard bow.
Not yet.
6,000 kilometers.
5,000.
3,000...2,000.
Now!
Initiating evasive maneuvers,
beta sequence.
Two more
Kazon ships approaching.
Shields at 90 percent.
( sighs deeply )
( muttering in alien language)
Janeway to Torres.
Initiate holo-programs.
Acknowledged.
Energizing.
That's two.
And here's number three.
( insistent beeping )
Help! Man overboard!
( screaming )
B'ELANNA:
Doctor, are you there?
Are you all right?
I told you
we should have run
one last systems check.
( sighs )
( rumble )
Fourth Kazon ship,
dead ahead.
But they're dividing
their fire, Captain.
The holograms
are working.
Ready photons.
Torpedoes loaded.
Take us about, Mr. Paris.
We want a good angle
on that fourth ship.
Coming about, 141 mark 20.
Fire photon number one.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Full starboard roll.
Evasive maneuvers,
lambda sequence.
Fire.
Shields at 85 percent
and holding.
Minor damage reported,
Deck 14.
Come about
to 143 mark 060.
Coming about.
Ready photons.
Dispersal pattern
sierra. Fire.
( yelling )
I'm reading a massive discharge
on Deck 8.
We've lost
a primary plasma conduit.
Deck 8-- Tierna's quarters.
Damage control teams
to Deck 8.
I'm showing power failures
all over the ship.
We've lost power
to the new holodeck grid.
I can't restore it.
B'Elanna,
are you all right?
Yes, Captain.
But it looks like
our reactant injector controls
were hit. Stand by.
All three Kazon ships
are concentrating
their fire on us now, Captain.
KIM:
Shields at 70 percent
and falling.
Starboard targeting
scanners are off-line.
Evasive maneuvers, Mr. Paris.
Gamma sequence.
Engineering,
I need warp power.
We can't go to warp,
Captain.
The containment field
generator has been damaged.
I'm attempting to bypass.
Captain, if I can get a shuttle
through the crossfire,
I can go back and bring
the Talaxians to help us.
Chakotay, take the conn.
Good luck, Lieutenant.
( suspenseful theme continues )
( rumbling, alarm beeps )
Shuttle is clear.
So far, so good.
Give him as much cover fire
as you can, Tuvok.
Aye, Captain.
( grunts )
( consoles beeping )
Voyager to Paris.
Please respond.
Tom, can you hear me?
I've lost contact
with the shuttle.
( rumbling continues )
Navigational array
is off-line.
We've lost power
to forward phasers.
Shields at 30 percent.
They're buckling.
( yelling )
Report.
The driver coil assembly
has been destroyed.
Impulse engines
are off-line.
TUVOK:
We're being boarded through
the shuttle bays, Captain.
Phaser fights reported
on Decks 5, 6, 7.
CHAKOTAY:
Intruder alert.
Security to
Decks 5 through 7.
Begin evacuation.
Janeway to computer.
( computer beeps )
Initiate
self-destruct sequence.
Authorization:
Janeway-pi-1-1-0.
Set at 10 minutes.
( computer beeps )
COMPUTER:
Unable to initiate
self-destruct sequence
due to damage to
secondary command processors.
MALE:
Stay where you are.
Don't move!
( grunts )
Hold your fire.
Get down there!
You! Move!
( ominous theme playing )
I want to speak to
Maje Culluh.
CULLUH:
Easily arranged, Captain.
Hello, everyone.
What do you think
of your son, Chakotay?
He has your eyes.
Don't you think?
Thank goodness
he doesn't look too human.
You all have
such weak foreheads.
May he grow up never knowing
the contempt his father has
for his mother.
I think I can assure you
of that, Commander.
I intend to take him
for my own son.
A man who would
violate a woman
under his own command--
What?
Doesn't deserve a son.
Is that what she told you?
The boy will be trained
as a Nistrim askara.
Already he has helped us win the
greatest battle in our history.
JANEWAY:
Culluh.
I'd like to discuss
what happens now.
( grunts )
You'll be given no more respect
than any Kazon woman...
now that your ship
and technology are mine.
I will tell you
when you may speak.
Allow my crew to live.
They were following
my orders.
You're even worse than she is.
What is it about the women
from your Quadrant?
You know she contradicts me
in front of the senior askara?
My own woman, disputing
her maje in front of others.
This is your fault.
You've let your women
get out of control.
You know you have
my deepest respect, Maje.
Why is it so dark in here?
Somebody turn on the lights.
Order the repair crews
to begin work immediately.
I want to leave
for the Hanon system
as soon as possible.
What's in the Hanon system?
Your new home.
Take them to a cargo bay.
Have the whole crew
brought there.
Check all quarters.
( snaps fingers )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Move.
( grunts )
Good-bye, Chakotay.
I'll take good care
of our son.
( baby crying )
Oh, are you hungry,
my brave little boy?
( Kazon indistinctly
yelling commands )
You! Move!
Keep moving!
NEELIX: This is outrageous!
KAZON MALE: Shut up!
Get up! Move!
Get out!
Computer, activate
medical holographic recall.
Set for 12 hours.
Mark.
( computer beeps )
Check every room.
In here.
Get back.
( grunting )
( people grunting )
KAZON MALE:
Keep moving!
( suspenseful theme continues )
Essential repairs
are complete, Maje.
We have accounted for
all but two
of the Federation crew.
There is also
a shuttle missing.
Yes, we destroyed the shuttle
as it was leaving.
Has that been confirmed?
Fine.
Have the other ships
send out search parties.
Confirm the shuttle
was destroyed.
And even if they
find wreckage
that seems to be
from the shuttle,
tell them to check
for a recent warp trail.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Stand by to engage
atmospheric thrusters.
Prepare for landing.
Activate the viewscreen.
Extend landing struts.
( rumbling )
Ready environmental controls!
( rumble )
Disengage engines.
Secure thruster exhaust.
( laughing )
Badges.
Over here.
A fitting end for a people
who would not share
their technology.
Let's see if you manage
to survive...
without it.
( suspenseful theme playing )
All right.
Let's go.
We've got to find
water and shelter.
We'll divide
the crew into teams.
Each of you
will be a team leader.
Make it clear
to all your people
that we expect
to be rescued
and our job
is to survive
until help arrives.
Do you really think
it's likely
that someone will
find us, Captain?
You're the morale
officer, Neelix.
You give me an answer.
Help is on the way!
Maybe Tom's shuttle
got through.
It's very important
that this crew
be given
a sense of hope.
That's our most important
job right now.
Our top priority
is drinking water.
Second is shelter
to spend the night.
CHAKOTAY:
A clearing
with a protected side
like the base of
a cliff would be best.
Food, fuel-- Look for all
the basic survival requirements.
That includes anything that can
be used as a tool or a weapon.
We'll reconvene here
in about two hours.
All right,
start dividing the crew.
Looks like we don't have
much daylight left.
We'll spread the teams out
in a standard
alpha search pattern
to see what we have
to work with.
Chakotay, Torres,
you're with me.
Alpha team here.
Beta team, this way.
KIM:
Gamma team.
Delta team with me.
( rumble )
The planet seems to be
seismically active.
At first glance,
it's an M-Class planet
in a Pliocene stage
of evolution.
Comparable to Earth
several million years ago.
( engines powering up )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( rumbling growl )
Captain.
( engines roaring )
( suspenseful theme continues )
( triumphant theme playing )