NARRATOR:
Last time on
Star Trek Voyager...
Chakotay, they're
going to take your son...
when Culluh saw,
the baby wasn't his.
Please, help us,
not for me, for your son.
CULLUH:
I told you
to stay out of here.
No!
I have a duty to this crew.
I can't just leave and go
looking for the child.
And I'd never consider
letting you go
into a Kazon-Nistrim
stronghold by yourself.
Captain, if I can get a shuttle
through the cross fire
I can go back and bring
the Talaxians to help us.
We're being boarded through
the shuttle bays, Captain.
MALE:
Stay where you are. Don't move.
Hold your fire.
Computer, activate
medical holograph recall.
Set for 12 hours.
Mark.
A fitting end for a people
who would not share
their technology.
Let's see if you
manage to survive
without it.
We'll divide
the crew into teams.
Each of you will
be a team leader.
Make it clear to all your people
that we expect to be rescued.
And now the conclusion.
CHAKOTAY:
Let me help you.
No, really,
I'm all right.
Don't push yourself.
That goes for everyone.
Perspiring wastes water.
( rumbling )
JANEWAY:
All right, people, follow me.
Let's take it slow.
This is the most
defensible location
we've seen so far.
The overhang should
provide us with shelter
and the breeze
should keep insects away.
All right,
let's make camp.
Neelix, look at this.
They almost look constructed.
Maybe the people on this world
are cave dwellers.
If that's true,
I'd say this is
a "do not disturb" sign.
Wouldn't you?
They look humanoid.
We might be able to use these
as tools or weapons.
Gather them up,
Mr. Hogan.
Is there a problem?
No, sir.
Do you want all of them?
Waste nothing.
That's one of the first rules
of survival.
FEMALE:
Neelix, over here.
( distant thud )
( creature breathing heavily )
( Hogan screams )
NEELIX:
Hogan!
Computer,
repeat stabilizer diagnostic.
Damage has been detected
in the stabilizer
acceleration sensors.
I just repaired
the acceleration sensors.
Warning.
Vessel approaching
on intercept course.
Signature.
Kazon patrol vessel.
Damn it, I don't
have time for this.
I don't have time for this!
Computer, all stop.
Engage impulse.
I told you,
I don't have time for this.
CHAKOTAY:
It's all that's left
of Hogan's uniform, Captain.
We didn't find anything else.
NEELIX:
This is my fault.
If I hadn't told Hogan
to pick up those bones...
You shouldn't blame
yourself, Neelix.
JANEWAY:
Stop it. There's no time
to worry about blame.
Hogan was a fine officer
and a good man.
And our job is
to make sure his death
is the last one
for a long time.
I will not let this planet
destroy my crew.
Kes, see to it
that everyone knows
the tunnels
are off limits.
I want clear safety
protocols established.
Mr. Tuvok,
we need weapons.
I have already begun to design
some rudimentary devices,
Captain.
What's our food
and water status?
I know it sounds grisly
but I can make solar stills
with the material
from this uniform.
We could have
water tomorrow.
Do it.
Captain,
none of the search teams
were able to find plants
of any nutritional value.
Then tell the crew to start
turning over rocks.
If anyone balks at eating these,
tell them it's an order
from their captain.
They may be the difference
between life and death.
Activate emergency medical
holographic program.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency?
Hello, doctor.
Remember me?
How could I forget
such an intriguing
medical mystery?
A Bajoran crewman with
a Cardassian physiology.
How are you, Seska?
( baby crying )
I see we have
a new passenger.
Doctor, I have to inform you
about a change of command.
I'm curious how you'll react.
The Kazon-Nistrim
have taken voyager.
How interesting.
Does your program have
any problem with that?
One humanoid is pretty
much the same as another
from a holographic
point of view.
I'm programmed
to provide medical care
to anyone who needs it.
Tell me, is it within your
program's capabilities
to lie or be deceptive?
I've learned that
a bedside manner
occasionally
requires me to--
how shall I put it--
soft-pedal the truth.
But bald-faced lying,
calculated deceit--
I don't have much experience
with that sort of thing.
But my program is adaptive.
If you really need me
to be deceptive
I'm sure I could learn.
It's not exactly
what I meant.
I think we'll keep you
just as you are.
As you wish.
Your baby's in good health.
You don't know how primitive
Kazon medicine is.
I'm sure Chakotay would be glad
to know you're
looking after his son.
Chakotay's son?
That isn't Chakotay's son.
But you're wrong, doctor.
I impregnated myself
with his DNA.
That may have been
your intention...
but it certainly
wasn't the result.
Here.
See for yourself.
Your child has
Cardassian DNA strands here
and Kazon DNA here.
Human DNA has
a significantly different
nucleotide sequence.
( crying )
But I was so certain.
He looks...
He's the first offspring
of a Cardassian
and a Kazon.
We have no frame
of reference
by which to judge
his initial appearance.
Perhaps he will develop
more Kazon features
as he matures.
Maje Culluh
will be so pleased.
End medical
holographic program.
Medical log, stardate 50032.7.
I have determined
that Commander Chakotay
is not the father
of Seska's child.
I only wish there was
some way to inform him.
What am I supposed to do--
lead a revolt with
the gang from Sandrine's?
Conjure up holograms
of Nathan Hale and Che Guevara?
I'm a doctor,
not a counterinsurgent.
Get a hold of yourself.
You're not just a hologram.
You're a Starfleet hologram.
Maybe...
Maybe I could access
a tactical database--
teach myself guerilla warfare.
But that would take time.
Computer, what is
the crew complement?
There are 89 Kazon...
89...
and one Betazoid on board.
What did you say? Betazoid?
There is one Betazoid on board.
Where? Who?
Please restate
a single question.
Who is it?
Crewman Lon Suder.
Suder?
Where is he?
Between decks eight and nine.
Doctor to Suder.
Yes.
Yes, doctor, I hear you.
The ship has been taken over
by the Kazon-Nistrim.
I know.
I've been hiding.
Can you make it to sick bay?
I think so.
Computer, emergency
medical priority, 1-1-4.
Delete the signature
of Mr. Suder's combadge
from the system. There is to be
no record of his being on board.
JANEWAY:
Huddle together in groups.
That'll preserve body heat.
This is no time to be shy.
Tuvok...
KIM:
Captain, how do you
like your eggs?
TORRES:
We found a nest
about two kilometers away.
And that's not all--
Cucumbers,
or something like them.
There are vines full of them
two hours from here.
Take them to Neelix,
and tell him to hold off
on the beetle stew,
at least for the time being.
How's she doing, Samantha?
I don't know, Captain.
She seems tired, listless.
JANEWAY:
Maybe she's just adjusting
to the environment.
After all,
she was born in space.
Make sure you
stay close to the fire...
as soon as we have one.
( scraping )
Trapped on a barren planet,
and you're stuck with the
only Indian in the universe
who can't start a fire by
rubbing two sticks together.
I was never good at this as a
child and I'm still not.
Don't be so hard on yourself,
none of the others have had
any success with it either.
It must be the wood.
We need kindling of some sort.
What?
Something my father once told me
about starting a fire.
There you go.
If we put some bigger
rocks around the fire
they'll reflect
the heat better.
I'm going to go get some.
Neelix!
You shouldn't go
too far away from camp!
Voyager's been taken by
the Kazon-Nistrim.
They're flooding every subspace
frequency with the news.
Is there any word on the crew?
I'm afraid not.
If you can help me with repairs
we can be on our way
in a few hours.
Lieutenant... our ships
are no match for Voyager,
and your shuttlecraft
can hardly--
Commander Paxim,
my people are counting on you.
Look, no one knows Voyager
like I do .
I know every vulnerability,
every blind spot.
Don't worry. I have a plan.
( sighs )
Very well.
We'll rendezvous in an hour.
Paxim out.
One hour.
I should be able to come up with
some kind of plan in one hour.
I was beginning to think
you'd gotten lost.
I'm sorry.
They're still
repairing the ship.
I had to be careful.
We have no time to waste.
According to the computer,
we're at warp.
We've got to slow down before we
get too far from the crew.
That would seem to be
our first priority.
And then we have
to get some weapons...
Mr. Suder,
are you listening to me?
Yes.
Oh.
I see.
Perhaps you consider this...
an opportunity.
Opportunity?
To obtain
your freedom from confinement.
How foolish of me to think
you would want to help.
You're wrong.
I do want to help.
Then... what?
I'm going to have
to kill some of them.
It is possible.
Violence might be required
to retake the ship.
I've worked so...
so hard over
the last few months...
to control the violent feelings.
I'm almost at peace with myself.
I mean, I see the day coming
when I could be.
Mr. Suder...
if Lieutenant Tuvok were here
I know he would tell you
there are times
when violence is required
to defend yourself,
to defend your ship,
to defend your crew.
Yes.
There is a logical use
for violence for everyone else.
With me,
once it begins...
we must do this
together, Mr. Suder.
If you don't trust
yourself yet, then trust me.
I will help you
any way I can.
One hologram
and one sociopath
may not be much
of a match for the Kazon,
but we'll have to do.
There are signs of a struggle
near the edge of camp.
I found alien tracks.
We can't wait until
morning to go after them.
Well I'm better at tracking
than starting fires.
I've completed a few weapons
that might be appropriate,
Commander.
This is thoughtful
of you, Tuvok.
But my tribe never
used bows and arrows
and I've never even shot one.
This is mine.
I taught archery science
for several years
at the Vulcan Institute
of Defensive Arts.
Take as many crew
members as you need.
( grunting )
Tus.
Filhin hissen.
Now, see here.
You just keep
your hands off her.
Toru hin!
Dart hin cahi filhir.
Tirk hir pahin!
( screams )
Shod!
Kuwissu hir. Shod!
Commander,
thank goodness.
Are you all right?
KES:
They haven't
hurt us.
Have you been able to tell if
they have a leader?
I'd say it's the one
with the claw.
NEELIX:
I agree. The other two seem
to be trying to figure out
what to make of us.
In a manner of speaking, not
in the culinary sense, I hope.
Listen to the sound
of my voice
and you'll know that
I mean you no harm.
I come without weapons.
But I must have
my people back.
Shod!
Kuwissu hir!
Toru hin!
Lam!
Tolun...
kusettun hatru.
Thank you...
but she should
stay with you.
I must take them with me.
Kuman khahun hin!
Dert hissen sahk!
Stand? Certainly,
I'll be happy to stand.
Over here. Fine.
Chim kan issen sahk.
What?
No. No!
That is unacceptable.
Kes, stand up slowly,
and walk away with us.
We have to go now.
Kukhahun hin.
Just keep walking.
Don't look back.
Kha hin!
In there.
Commander, that looks just
like the tunnel where Hogan...
I know.
If they know it, too,
they won't follow us in.
Come on.
You'd think this crew had never
seen a warp drive before.
No one tried to adjust
the antimatter flow today?
No one.
If you're lying,
I'll have your head.
I swear it, Maje.
There should have
been some warning
before the antimatter
injector froze--
a drop in core temperature,
a magnetic constriction alarm,
something.
He's either lying or...
Or what?
Computer, run a level one
scan for intruders.
Unable to comply.
Internal scanner relays
have been damaged.
I thought you said all
repairs were complete.
They were.
I thought they were.
I want a
deck-by-deck search
of all Jeffries tubes
and conduits.
Use the Federation tricorders.
Do you have a portable
thoron generator?
Yes, of course.
We use it to treat
radiation burns.
It's an old Maquis trick.
Thoron particles neutralize
tricorder sensors.
Mr. Suder,
we need some weapons
if we're going
to retake the ship.
( crying )
She has a fever.
I don't know what to do.
Let me get her
some water.
( rumbling )
The baby needs water.
Those tremors seem
to be getting stronger.
Chakotay's team should
have been back by now.
We better look for them
before it gets too hot.
Get a few people together.
I'll join you in a second.
( all shouting )
Come on. We have to see if
there's another way out of here.
( rumbling )
KES:
I feel a breeze.
It's coming
from this way.
( chanting )
Do you really think
Commander Chakotay
would go in there after
what happened to Hogan?
He may have had
no other choice.
How do we get them
away from the tunnels?
A couple of phaser blasts
would do the trick.
Who are the fastest
runners here?
TORRES:
I was on
the decathlon team
before I quit the academy.
The track and field coach
was furious with me.
Anyone else here who can run?
Yeah.
Okay, you three will
be the sprint team.
Once you reach our camp,
you should be safe.
Which way
do you like, Tuvok?
From a tactical
point of view
the options are
not encouraging.
However, moving
past the creature
might lead us
to an exit.
All right,
let's take it slow.
Single file.
TORRES:
Hey, up here!
Up here!
You want us?
Come and get us.
Come on, come and get us.
( shouting )
Pull this.
( creature breathing )
( grunts )
( creature grunts )
( yelling )
( creature growling distantly )
JANEWAY:
Chakotay!
Tuvok!
KIM:
The tunnel's clear.
Go!
Everybody out!
Move! Let's go!
Go! Go! Go!
Go!
Chakotay, your spear.
Come on. Come on, go!
CHAKOTAY:
Come on.
I don't understand it.
Thoron particles are leaking
into the conduits
from somewhere.
I can't get
any other readings.
Check the next level.
Yes, sir.
COMPUTER:
Incoming subspace message
on the emergency medical
holographic channel.
On the emergency channel?
Doc, I hope you're
receiving this,
because if you're not,
I'm a dead duck.
I'm piggy-backing this message
on a fake Kazon signal
I'm sending to the bridge.
I'm betting
they won't be monitoring
your emergency medical channel.
I'm bringing help.
But you have
to do something for us.
When the attack begins
I need you to get the computer
to block the discharge
from the backup
phaser power couplings.
You got that?
The backup couplings.
I'm taking out
the primary couplings myself.
But I need those backups
to overload
when they switch to them.
Don't do anything
until the attack begins,
or they might notice.
That's it for now.
I'll be seeing you soon.
I hope.
( thud )
Good news.
Help is on the way.
Mr. Paris apparently
was able to...
Oh.
I didn't know
what to do.
I didn't think I
should leave him there
where they could find him.
Of course, you were smart
to bring him here.
We can put him
in a stasis drawer.
Well, we have weapons now.
You did what was
necessary, Mr. Suder.
Five cc's of improvoline
will help you calm down.
SUDER:
No. No drugs.
I just need to breathe--
see the white light
that is my breath.
We just received
a message
from our patrol ship.
They've tracked down
the shuttle from Voyager...
and destroyed it.
Were two people on board?
They didn't say.
Two people were unaccounted for
when we captured the crew.
Have they found any evidence
of an intruder on board?
No.
But the search has been slowed
down by a thoron particle leak.
Thoron particles?
That's an old Maquis trick
to fool tricorders.
TUVOK:
After what transpired,
I believe we have to
prepare ourselves for
an alien attack, Captain.
Our priority should be to
increase the weapons arsenal
and to begin training everyone
in the use of these weapons.
I don't like the sound of that,
Lieutenant.
We may have to coexist
with these aliens a long time.
Nevertheless...
CHAKOTAY:
I agree with the Captain.
We have to find a way
to share this world with them.
You may find nobility
in a savage, Commander,
but he is only interested
in killing you.
I don't believe that.
KES:
Captain!
The baby is very sick.
She's having trouble breathing.
She has a high fever. There's
nothing more I can do for her.
( rumbling )
Captain!
I think our top priority
has just been dictated.
Break camp. We've got to get out
of here before it blows.
Why are you still here?
I shut down your
program when I left.
You must be mistaken.
Where's your
thoron generator?
It was damaged on a recent away
mission and left behind.
Who else from Voyager
is on board ?
I wouldn't know.
I don't believe you.
There are several dozen
crewman on board actually,
and they have been
working around the clock
to sabotage your vessel.
That's a lie.
At most, there is one,
and I believe
it is a Maquis crewman.
Yes, of course.
You're right.
It is one of the Maquis.
I won't play these games
with a trick of light.
Sticks and stones
won't break my bones,
so you can imagine
how I feel
about being called names.
I don't believe you could
have sabotaged this ship alone.
Very well.
Since you are obviously
about to disable
my program anyway,
let me take
the credit I deserve.
I did sabotage the ship
all by myself
with the computer's
help, of course.
As a matter of fact, one of your
crewman came in unexpectedly
and caught me in the act.
You killed him?
He left me no choice.
Why create a thoron leak
if you're not hiding someone?
I would think it's obvious,
to make you believe
I was hiding someone.
I've had your people
crawling through the bowels
of this ship for hours
looking for an intruder.
You're more talented
in the art of deception
than you led me to believe.
I was inspired
by the presence of a master.
Computer,
Access Culluh zero-one.
Disregard all
voice commands
from Starfleet
personnel.
Security lock-out.
( rumbling )
Seska to Bridge.
What's going on?
MALE:
A couple of Talaxian ships
have fired on us.
Nothing to worry about.
Good-bye, doctor.
I'd rather not take
any more chances.
( rumbling )
Doctor?
Activate emergency
medical holographic program.
Unable to respond.
All Starfleet voice access
has been canceled.
DOCTOR:
Mr. Suder,
if you are hearing this,
you have just
unsuccessfully attempted
to access the emergency
medical program.
I have programmed
this message to play
in the event
that I have been disabled.
This means, of course,
that the fate of Voyager
now depends solely on you.
I can imagine how you
must feel at this moment.
I want you to know
you have my full confidence.
You have already shown
great courage and dedication to
your crew.
I have left an
additional message for
Captain Janeway
and Lieutenant Tuvok
noting your heroism,
in case I am irretrievable.
You know what you have to do
and when to do it.
And I know that with our fate
in your hands
we will prevail.
Good luck, Mr. Suder.
The Talaxians are retreating
toward the nebula.
We'll teach them the price
for attacking the Nistrim.
Lay in
a pursuit course.
Commander Paxim to Paris.
Go ahead.
They're following us
as planned.
We're bringing them to you.
Acknowledged. Ready and waiting.
I just hope you are, too, doc.
JANEWAY:
This way.
( screams )
It's okay.
Here we go.
What's happening?!
Our phaser power couplings
are under attack.
From where?
I don't see anyone.
I'm not picking up anything
on the scanners.
Shields are buckling.
Take evasive action.
( groans )
I have it on the scanners.
It's a Federation shuttlecraft.
Lock phasers.
Destroy it.
Primary phaser
power is down.
Switch to backup systems.
Confirmed.
Phasers are locked on.
Fire!
I don't understand.
I'm showing an overload.
PARIS:
Yes, doc, yes.
Paris to Commander Paxim.
Stand by.
I'm going to start transporting
your people to Voyager.
Standing by.
( baby crying )
Seska!
Seska...
Engineering to Maje Culluh.
We're being boarded.
Abandon ship.
( baby crying )
I'm sealing off
the Bridge manually.
I've got to get
the computer back on-line.
All Starfleet voice access
has been disabled.
I'm reading a Kazon shuttle
leaving the ship.
There are also escape pods
being launched.
Forget them.
We have more important
things to do.
She's breathing
better, isn't she?
Sad katonk.
PARIS:
Welcome back, Captain.
Well done, Lieutenant.
I had a lot of help.
The Talaxians,
the doc, Mr. Suder.
KIM:
Suder?
We thought he was killed
during the initial attack.
No. He and the doctor
sabotaged the ship.
Suder disabled the phasers
before they killed him.
You would have been
proud of him, Mr. Tuvok.
I offer you
a Vulcan prayer, Mr. Suder.
May your death
bring you the peace
you never found in life.
Mr. Kim, is this ship capable
of sustained flight?
All propulsion and navigational
systems are functioning
within normal parameters,
Captain.
Good. Take us away
from our new home,
and set a course
for the old one, Mr. Paris.
Warp eight.
Heading 4-1 mark 7-7.
Destination:
Alpha quadrant.
Engage.