NEELIX:
Anthraxic citrus
peel orange juice
with just a hint of
papalla seed extract--
an experimental blend.
The success rate
of your culinary experiments
has not been high.
Ensign Golwat tried
some yesterday
and she thought
it was delicious.
In fact, she had
a second glass
and she never has seconds.
Ensign Golwat is Bolian.
Her tongue has
a cartilaginous lining.
It would protect her
against even the most
corrosive acid.
All I ask is that you
try it, Mr. Vulcan.
Impressive.
Ah.
I'll start squeezing
that second glass.
Breakfast is coming
right up.
Porakan eggs.
Porakan?
The most flavorful eggs
in the sector.
Scrambled
with a little dill weed,
a touch of rengazo--
a galactic favorite.
Now, these eggs
were not easy
to prepare.
After we picked them up
on Porakas IV,
I had to sterilize them
in a cryostatic chamber
for three days.
Then each and every one
had to be parboiled...
Mr. Neelix, I would prefer
not to hear the life history
of my breakfast.
On Talax, it's a tradition
to share the history of a meal
before you begin eating.
It's a way of enhancing
the culinary experience.
My mother was brilliant.
She could make every course,
every garnish come alive
by making it a character
in a story.
My favorite was the one
about the crustacean who...
What happened?
Um, some sort
of power overload.
I'm afraid it decimated
your breakfast.
This is what my mother
would have called
a tragic ending.
Engineering has been
making adjustments
to the plasma conduits
to accommodate a
new energy source.
It may have created
a thermal surge
in the galley systems.
Janeway to Tuvok.
Please report to the Bridge.
Mr. Neelix, I'd like you
to join us as well.
Aye, Captain.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
stardate 50126.4.
We have detected
a gaseous anomaly
that contains sirillium--
a highly combustible
and versatile energy source.
We've altered course
to investigate.
Sirillium?
Yes, and possibly
large amounts of it.
If so, we're going
to need to stockpile
as much as we can.
I'd like to convert
Storage Bay 3
into a containment
chamber.
My pantry.
I'm sorry, Neelix.
You're going to have to
make other arrangements.
Of course, Captain.
You know,
if I injected sirillium
into my thermal array,
it might improve cooking time.
Yes, and blow up half your
kitchen in the process.
Sirillium is far more useful
as a warp plasma catalyst.
The gas can also be used
to boost
deflector shield efficiency.
The vultures
are circling.
Well, there's certainly
no shortage of good ideas.
Have all department heads
submit proposals
for sirillium usage.
Aye, Captain.
TUVOK:
The anomaly is
within visual range.
On screen.
Analysis, Mr. Kim.
It's a class-17 nebula.
I'm detecting
standard amounts
of hydrogen and helium
and 7,000 parts per
million of sirillium.
TORRES:
Captain, I
recommend we use
the Bussard collectors
to gather the sirillium.
They'll cut through that
nebula like ice cream scoops.
PARIS:
I'm picking up
a lot of plasmatic
turbulence in there.
It might be a bumpy ride.
JANEWAY:
Tuvok, can you modify the
shields to compensate?
Tuvok...
Are you all right,
Lieutenant?
I don't know.
I'm experiencing dizziness
and...
disorientation.
Permission to go to Sick Bay.
Granted.
( door opening )
Deck 5.
GIRL:
Help me!
Tuvok!
Help me, Tuvok!
GIRL:
Please, don't let go!
Tuvok!
Don't let me fall!
( panting )
No!
( door opens )
( panting heavily )
I was holding a young girl
by the hand,
trying to prevent her
from falling from a precipice.
I was unable to keep my grip,
and she fell to her death.
And there is more.
I had an emotional response--
anxiety, fear--
an almost irrational
anger at myself
for letting her fall.
When did that happen?
It never happened.
The girl was unfamiliar
and I've never been
in that situation.
It was me as a child
and it did seem
like a memory,
but I don't recall
the incident.
Well, it was definitely
a traumatic episode.
Your heart rate
accelerated
to 300 beats per minute
your adrenaline levels
rose by 113 percent
and your neuroelectrical
readings
nearly jumped off the scale.
If you were human, I'd say
you had a severe panic attack.
I am not human.
No kidding.
I don't know
what happened to you,
but there can be any number
of explanations--
hallucination, telepathic
communication from another race,
repressed memory,
momentary contact
with a parallel reality.
Take your pick.
The universe is
such a strange place.
JANEWAY:
I'll have Mr. Kim
examine the sensor logs.
Maybe our proximity
to the nebula
is affecting you somehow.
In the meantime, Lieutenant,
you are free to go.
All of your vital signs
have returned to normal
and I don't see any
residual systemic damage.
But I want you to wear
this neurocortical monitor.
In case you have
another episode,
it'll record a complete
encephalographic profile
and alert Sick Bay
at the same time.
A wise precaution,
Doctor.
Thank you.
TUVOK:
Structure.
Logic.
Function.
Control.
A structure cannot stand
without a foundation.
Logic is the foundation
of function.
Function...
is the essence of control.
I am in control.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Kes.
What is it?
The Doctor wanted
me to adjust your
neurocortical monitor to pick
up additional peptide readings.
I can come back later
if this is a bad time.
No.
You may proceed.
What are you
working on?
It is called a keethara.
Keethara?
What does that mean?
The approximate translation
is "structure of harmony."
It is used as a mediational aid.
Building it
requires precise balance
and spatial acuity.
It helps to focus thought
and refine
mental control.
At the moment, it doesn't
look very harmonious.
No. It does not.
I'm curious.
What does a keethara
look like when it's done?
The form is not predefined.
It is a reflection
of the builder's state of mind.
Thus, it is
different each time.
I'd like to see it
when it's finished.
Well, good night.
Kes...
It's all right.
I understand.
Structure.
Logic.
Function.
Control.
A structure cannot stand
without a foundation.
Logic is the foundation...
of function.
Function is the essence
of control.
I am in control.
I am in... control.
CHAKOTAY:
So how are you feeling
this morning?
If you are referring
to yesterday's incident,
I haven't experienced
any further problems.
I am fit for duty.
I didn't ask
because I'm concerned
about your ability
to perform.
I'm concerned
about you.
There is no need
for concern.
Sorry I asked.
My apologies, Commander.
I am distracted.
I spent 14 hours
last night
in deep meditation
trying to determine
the source of my aberrant
behavior. I could not.
Maybe you should try to forget
about it for a while.
I've found that when you
don't think about a problem,
sometimes the solution
comes to you.
It is difficult
to forget
when you're wearing a
neurocortical monitor
on your parietal bone.
Good point.
Mr. Kim?
I checked all the sensor logs.
There's no sign of anything
emanating from the nebula
that would have
affected Tuvok or Voyager.
Anything unusual
about the nebula itself?
No. It's a standard
class-17.
I suggest we conduct
a tachyon sweep
of the nebula.
It would reveal the presence
of any cloaked ships.
Cloaked ships?
Yes. We should be
extremely cautious
this close to Klingon space.
Tuvok, the Klingon Empire
is on the other side
of the galaxy.
Yes. Yes, you are
right, of course.
I'm uncertain why I would
make such an obvious error.
Maybe you should go
back to Sick Bay.
Tuvok?
Help me, Tuvok!
Please, don't let go!
No!
I think we may be dealing
with a repressed memory.
The memory engrams
in the dorsal region
of the hippocampus
are being disrupted.
It's causing physical
damage to the
surrounding tissue.
In Vulcan medicine,
this is known
as t'lokan schism.
It means that
the subject
is inhibiting
a traumatic memory,
which is beginning
to resurface.
And that's causing
brain damage?
Strange, I know.
In human subjects,
repressed memories
are nothing more than
psychological traumas,
which can be dealt
with with standard
therapeutic techniques,
but in Vulcans,
there is a physical reaction
to the battle between
the conscious and
the unconscious.
In extreme cases,
the mind of the patient
can literally...
lobotomize itself.
What's the treatment?
There is no medical treatment
for this condition.
Vulcan psychocognitive
research suggests
that the patient initiate
a mind-meld with a family member
and the two of them
attempt to bring
the repressed memory
into the conscious mind.
I'm the closest thing
Tuvok has to a family
member on this ship.
That's why I've
asked you to come.
He has a request
to make of you.
Did the Doctor explain
the situation to you?
Yes.
Tuvok, are you sure it's
the right thing to do?
I don't know
how else to proceed.
The Doctor tells me
that this is a memory.
And yet, no matter
how hard I try,
I cannot remember.
If the Doctor is correct,
if this is an experience
I pushed into
my unconscious mind,
it could be
very dangerous to me,
even life-threatening.
I realize it's asking
a great deal of you, Captain,
and I did consider turning
to one of the Vulcans
on the ship,
but this meld would be
more intimate than most.
A family member
is normally chosen
because of the implicit trust
that usually exists.
On this ship...
I trust you
more than anyone else.
Whatever happens,
I'll be there
for you, Tuvok.
I'll help you
get through this.
I will initiate the meld
and attempt to access
the memory fragment.
Once that has been
accomplished,
you will act
as my pyllora.
Your pyllora.
My guide.
My counselor.
You will help me reconstruct
the memory in its entirety.
And as I am reliving it,
you will help me to
objectify the experience.
By processing the experience
rather than repressing it,
I can begin to overcome
my fear, anger
and the other
emotional responses
and to reintegrate
the memory
into my conscious mind.
When I'm in your memory,
will I actually be
reliving it with you?
No.
I will be the only one
who notices your presence.
You will be an observer
in the memory
but not a participant.
This will give
you the freedom
to guide me
objectively.
When do we start?
I will need time to prepare.
Please return in one hour.
We're ready when
you are, Captain.
Your mind to my mind.
Your thoughts...
to my thoughts.
I am taking us back...
back to the boy
that I was...
the boy lying
on the precipice.
( alarm blaring )
MAN:
Return fire!
MAN 2:
They've knocked out
our targeting scanners.
( indistinct voices )
TUVOK:
Mr. Valtane...
( alarm continues )
Get away
from that station!
VALTANE:
One more second.
( explosion )
MAN:
Damage report!
Seal that conduit!
Hull breach on Deck 12,
Section 47.
We've lost power
on Decks 5, 6 and 10.
Casualty reports coming in.
19 wounded.
Tuvok, can you see me?
Yes.
Where are we?
My first deep
space assignment
aboard the Excelsior.
Why did you bring us here?
I did not intend to.
Can you take us
to the precipice?
The girl?
That is precisely
what I attempted to do.
There must be some reason
why your mind brought us here.
Maybe this memory
is connected
to the girl in some way.
How long ago is this?
Stardate 9521.
Approximately 80 years ago.
Who are you fighting?
The Klingons.
Klingons?
Before you collapsed
in Engineering,
you thought we were
approaching Klingon space.
Why are you fighting
the Klingons?
This battle was precipitated
by an incident that took
place three days earlier.
All right, Gamma Shift
time to defend
the Federation
against gaseous anomalies.
Gaseous anomalies?
We were charting
a gaseous anomaly on Voyager.
And that's when
my problem began.
That's more than a coincidence.
How are you this
morning, Ensign?
I am well, Commander.
Thank you.
I thought you
might like to see
some of this morning's
com traffic
before you went on duty.
There's a message
from the Yorktown
I think you might
be interested in.
It's from your father.
Thank you.
You're not going to have
time to drink that, you know.
You're due on the
Bridge in five minutes.
It's not for me.
It's for the Captain.
I've observed
that Captain Sulu
drinks a cup of tea
each morning.
I thought he might enjoy
a Vulcan blend.
Oh, I see.
Trying to make Lieutenant
in your first month?
I wish I'd have
thought of that
when I was your age.
Took me three years
just to make Ensign.
I assure you I have
no ulterior motive.
Whatever you
say, Ensign.
See you on the Bridge.
You've never
brought me tea.
Outstanding.
I may have to give
you a promotion.
That was not my
motivation, Captain.
I am not attempting
to curry favor
with you in any way.
Mr. Tuvok, if you're going
to remain on my ship,
you're going
to have to learn
how to appreciate a joke.
And don't tell me Vulcans
don't have a sense of humor
because I know better.
I will... work
on it, sir.
Very good.
And... thanks again.
He doesn't
look anything
like his portrait
at Starfleet
Headquarters.
In the 23rd century,
holographic imaging resolution
was less accurate.
This is a science
station, isn't it?
Yes. I am one of several
junior science officers.
Tuvok, why doesn't
your service record
reflect any of this?
I thought your
first assignment
was aboard the Wyoming.
It's a long story, Captain,
but suffice it to say,
this was my first
Starfleet career.
I was 29 years old.
So, what's happening?
Are we about to encounter
the Klingons?
Not exactly.
The Klingon moon Praxis
is about to explode.
Praxis.
During this period, it was
a primary source of energy
for the Klingon Homeworld.
Praxis... yes.
Its destruction would
have lasting repercussions
throughout the Quadrant,
and it led to the first
Federation-Klingon
peace treaty.
That is correct.
But what does all
this have to do
with the girl
on the precipice?
( beeping )
I have an energy wave at 240
degrees, mark 6 port, sir.
Visual.
My... God!
Shields! Shields!
( yelling )
MAN:
She is not
answering the helm.
Starboard thrusters.
Turn her into the wave.
Aye, sir.
Quarter impulse power.
Damage report.
MAN:
Checking all
systems, Captain.
Don't tell me
that was any meteor shower.
Negative, sir.
The subspace shock wave
originated
at bearing 323 mark 75.
Location...
It's Praxis, sir.
It's a Klingon moon.
Praxis...
is their key energy
production facility.
So, what happened?
Did you go to Praxis?
No. We were warned off
by the Klingons
and resumed
our survey mission.
However, two days later,
we learned that two
Starfleet officers
were accused of murdering
the Klingon Chancellor.
They were brought back
to the Klingon Homeworld
to stand trial.
Captain Sulu had served
under both officers
for many years,
and he felt
an intense loyalty to them.
Helm, set a course
for Kronos, maximum warp.
Take us through
the Azure Nebula.
That should conceal
our approach.
Aye, sir.
I don't get it.
What's going on?
He's about to
attempt a rescue
of Captain Kirk
and Dr. McCoy.
As you can see,
everyone seemed
perfectly willing
to go along with this
breach of orders.
However, I felt
differently.
Captain, am I correct
in assuming
that you have decided to embark
on a rescue mission?
That's right.
Do you have a problem
with that, Ensign?
I do.
It is a direct violation
of our orders
from Starfleet Command,
and it could precipitate
an armed conflict
between the Klingon Empire
and the Federation.
Objection noted.
Resume your station.
Sir, as a Starfleet officer,
it is my duty
to formally protest.
Tuvok...
A pretty bold statement
for an Ensign
with only... two months
space duty under his belt?
I am aware
of my limited experience,
but I am also very much aware
of Starfleet regulations
and my obligation
to carry them out.
That's enough.
Ensign, you're relieved.
I'm sorry about
this, Captain.
I assure you it will
not happen again.
Ensign,
you're absolutely right,
but you're also...
absolutely wrong.
You'll find
that more happens
on the Bridge
of a starship than just
carrying out orders
and observing regulations.
There's a sense of loyalty
to the men and women
you serve with...
a sense of family.
Those two men
on trial--
I served with them
for a long time.
I owe them my life
a dozen times over,
and right now,
they're in trouble
and I'm going to help them.
Let the regulations be damned.
Sir, that is a most illogical
line of reasoning.
You better believe it.
Helm, engage.
You know, you did
the right thing.
Perhaps.
CREWMAN:
Captain, we're approaching
the Azure Nebula.
SULU:
On screen.
Tuvok...
that nebula...
it looks very similar
to the one
we observed on Voyager.
Help me, Tuvok!
Please, don't let go!
No!
( Tuvok gasps )
( instrument beeping )
50 milligrams cordrazine.
DOCTOR:
There was a sudden disruption
in his hippocampus.
Luckily,
he was in Sick Bay
or he'd be in a
coma right now.
That's the good news.
The bad news is that
his synaptic pathways
are continuing to degrade.
If the repressed memory
keeps resurfacing on its own,
it's going to
cause more and more damage.
His entire neural structure will
collapse,
resulting in brain death.
We were just starting
to make some progress.
We finally accessed
the repressed memory.
I saw Tuvok as a boy...
and the girl
on the precipice.
Can I talk to him?
Not yet.
He suffered a severe
neural trauma,
so I'm keeping him sedated
for the next few hours.
I'll let you know when
it's safe to revive him.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Ah, Ensign, what
have you found?
I don't see any connection
between this nebula
and the one the Excelsior
saw 80 years ago.
This one's a class-17,
while theirs was an 11.
Both contained trace
amounts of sirillium,
but that's about all.
But they do look similar.
To the naked eye,
but not to sensors.
Technically, they're
very different.
You know, I've been
talking to the Doctor,
and he tells me it's not
unusual for a repressed memory
to resurface because
of a smell or a visual detail.
Maybe the visual similarities
between the two nebulas
simply triggered Tuvok's
memory of the Excelsior.
Well, what about the
memory of the little girl?
What does she have to do
with Tuvok's experiences
on board Sulu's ship?
The Excelsior seemed
so far removed from
that childhood incident.
Who knows what goes on
in a Vulcan's mind?
Maybe there is no connection
and going back to the memory
of the Excelsior
was just an accident, a stray
thought Tuvok was having
because of the similarities
between the two nebulas.
You may be right.
Nevertheless, I've been
studying the Excelsior logs.
What do they say?
Unfortunately,
they don't say
anything at all.
Nothing?
It would seem that
Captain Sulu decided
not to enter that journey
into his official log.
The day's entry makes
some cryptic remark
about the ship being damaged
in a gaseous anomaly
and needing repairs
but nothing else.
You mean,
he falsified his logs.
It was a very different
time, Mr. Kim.
Captain Sulu, Captain
Kirk, Dr. McCoy--
they all belonged
to a different breed
of Starfleet officer.
Imagine the era they lived in--
the Alpha Quadrant
still largely unexplored,
humanity on verge
of war with Klingons,
Romulans hiding
behind every nebula.
Even the technology
we take for granted
was still in its
early stages.
No plasma weapons,
no multiphasic shields.
Their ships were
half as fast.
No replicators,
no holodecks.
You know, ever since I took
Starfleet history
at the Academy,
I always wondered
what it would be like
to live in those days.
Space must have seemed a
whole lot bigger back then.
It's not surprising they had
to bend the rules a little.
They were a little slower
to invoke the Prime Directive
and a little quicker
to pull their phasers.
Of course,
the whole bunch of them
would be booted
out of Starfleet today,
but I have to admit--
I would have loved to ride
shotgun at least once
with a group of officers
like that.
DOCTOR:
Sick Bay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Doctor.
I'm ready to revive Mr. Tuvok.
Acknowledged.
I'm on my way.
Several hours
after we entered the nebula,
we were ambushed by Klingons.
A battle ensued,
and we were forced
to abort our rescue mission.
Do any of those events
seem related to the girl
in any way?
No. If there is
a connection,
I am not aware of it.
I suggest we attempt
another mind-meld
and try again to access
my memory of the girl.
Agreed.
Doctor.
Your mind to my mind.
Your thoughts
to my thoughts.
I am taking us back--
back to the boy
that I was...
the boy lying
on the precipice.
RAND:
Hull breach on Deck 12,
Section 47.
Tuvok, we're back
in the battle
with the Klingons again,
80 years ago.
I am at a loss to
explain, Captain.
But it's hard to accept
this as a coincidence.
Agreed.
I want to go back
to the moment
when you first saw
the nebula.
What happened?
Captain Sulu estimated
it would take
approximately five hours
to traverse the nebula
and enter Klingon space.
He decided my shift
needed some rest,
so we returned to
the crew quarters.
I attempted to
get some sleep.
However, my bunkmate
Dmitri Valtane,
felt the need to discuss
our situation.
Hey.
Tuvok.
Are you asleep?
No.
Me neither.
I can't believe
we're going to do this.
I didn't think the Captain
had it in him.
Had what in him?
You know--
the guts to defy an order
and run off
on some rescue mission
to save old friends.
I take it from the tone
of your voice,
that you admire this trait.
Well, yeah.
It's courageous.
It is illogical
and reckless,
which I attempted to point
out to him on the Bridge.
Oh, come on, Tuvok.
Isn't it more fun than
charting gaseous anomalies?
The human fascination with
fun has led to many tragedies
in your short
but violent history.
One wonders how
your race has survived
having so much fun.
Ooh. Vulcans--
you guys need to relax.
No. I will not relax.
Ever since I entered
the Academy,
I've had to endure the
egocentric nature of humanity.
You believe that everyone in
the galaxy should be like you,
that we should all share
your sense of humor
and your human values.
Well, if you hate
it here so much,
why'd you join Starfleet
in the first place?
I joined under pressure
from my parents,
but I've already decided
to resign my commission
once this assignment
is complete.
( sighs )
Well, your loss.
Tuvok, did you
really mean that?
At this point
in my life, yes.
My experiences
at the Academy
and on board the Excelsior
were not pleasant.
I knew you
left Starfleet
for over 50 years,
but I never knew why.
I didn't realize
it was because
of a conflict
with humans.
My perceptions of humanity
and Starfleet
were undoubtedly
colored by the fact
that I did not want to be
here in the first place.
Your parents really forced
you to go to the Academy?
It was their wish
and I felt an obligation
to fulfill it.
What did you do
during those 50 years?
I'd returned to Vulcan
where I spent several
years in seclusion,
immersing myself
in the Kolinahr--
a rigorous discipline
intended to purge all emotions.
I wanted to attain a state
of pure and total logic.
What happened?
Unfortunately,
six years into my studies,
I began the Pon farr.
I took a mate.
T'Pel.
Yes.
We decided to raise
a family together.
So I chose to
postpone my studies.
And what brought you
back to Starfleet?
Raising children of my own
made me appreciate
what my parents
experienced raising me,
and I came to realize
that the decisions
I made as a young man
were not always
in my best interest.
I understood their decision
to send me to the Academy
and that there
were many things
I could learn from humans
and other species.
So I decided to expand
my knowledge of the galaxy.
Starfleet provided
that opportunity.
Well, I'm glad you
had a change of heart.
As am I, Captain.
Although, "heart" had
very little to do with it.
It was a logical decision.
I'm sure it was.
MALE:
Red Alert.
All hands to battle stations.
What's going on?
I thought we were still five
hours from Klingon space.
A Klingon battle cruiser
de-cloaked inside the nebula.
At this moment,
they were firing
concussive charges
across our bow.
RAND:
We're being
hailed, Captain.
On screen.
KANG:
Mr. Sulu,
I see they have finally given
you the Captaincy you deserve.
SULU:
Thank you, Kang.
Do not let it end prematurely.
Kang, we've been
on a survey mission
studying this nebula.
Our navigation system
malfunctioned
and I'm afraid we got lost.
As soon as we've completed
repairs, we'll be on our way.
We'd be happy to escort you
back to Federation space.
Very generous of you.
But we can manage.
I insist.
Actually, an escort
would be welcome.
We'd hate to lose our way again.
Bring your ship about,
bearing 181 mark 2.
Nice to see you again, Kang.
VALTANE:
Captain Sulu?
Man your station, Lieutenant.
We're not giving up just yet.
Helm, come about.
Tactical status.
They have their
forward disruptors
trained on us, sir.
Ensign Tuvok,
what is the composition
of this nebula?
Primarily oxygen and argon
with traces of theta-xenon,
fluorine and sirillium gas.
Sirillium?
That's a highly combustible
substance, isn't it?
Affirmative.
Is there any
way we could
ignite the sirillium?
If we modulated
a positron beam
to a subspace frequency,
it would trigger
a thermochemical reaction
in the sirillium.
Like tossing a match
into a pool of gasoline.
Would their shields
withstand
the blast?
Yes. But their sensors
and tactical systems
would be disrupted
for several seconds.
That's all
the time we need.
Tuvok, modulate a positron beam
and stand by.
We'll ignite the sirillium
the instant we clear the nebula.
Helm, prepare to engage
maximum warp on my command.
Aye, sir.
All hands, this is the Captain.
Secure stations
and batten down the hatches.
The positron beam
is charged and ready.
On my mark, Ensign.
We're clearing
the nebula.
Mr. Tuvok, light the match.
The Klingon ship's
been disabled.
They're not
pursuing, sir.
Helm, set a course
for Kronos.
Engage.
Commander Rand,
I want you...
Sir, long-range sensors
are detecting
three Klingon battle cruisers
on an intercept course.
They're arming
torpedoes.
Heading, sir?
Maintain course.
Return fire!
They've knocked out
our targeting scanners.
Switch to manual!
Mr. Valtane, there's a rupture
in the plasma conduit
behind your console.
Get away from that station.
One more second.
Dmitri, you must...
( yelling )
Bridge to Sick Bay,
medical emergency!
Tuvok...
Tuvok!
Help!
Don't let me fall!
No!
KES:
Doctor,
what's happening?
Their memory engrams
are destabilizing.
Something must be going
wrong with the mind-meld.
I'm going to bring
them out of it.
KES:
It's not working.
Their neural patterns
appear to be
locked together.
I can't break the meld.
The damage to his synaptic
patterns is accelerating.
At this rate, he'll be
brain dead in 20 minutes.
Get me a cortical
stimulator!
I saw her again, Tuvok--
the girl.
When Valtane
died just now,
it seemed to cause
the memory to resurface.
What is it?
Something's gone wrong
with the mind-meld.
Who the hell are you?
Intruder alert!
Get security up here!
What's happening?
Why can he see me?
SULU:
I asked you a question.
Who are you
and what are you
doing on my ship?
It's an indication
the rate of deterioration
in my brain has increased.
At advanced stages
of a t'lokan schism,
memories and thought processes
become distorted and confused.
Ensign, do you know this woman?
I will break the meld,
Captain.
No, don't.
I think we're getting
close to something.
Everything seems to be centered
around the death of Valtane.
( rumbling )
Direct hit on the port bow.
Shields down to 20 percent.
Losing atmosphere
on Decks 5, 6 and 7.
I'll reroute auxiliary power
to structural integrity.
( rumbling )
Maybe something happened
in that moment
between the two of you--
some detail you
aren't remembering.
I want you to try
and replay those events
one more time.
I will try,
but I must point out
that if my neural structures
collapse during the meld,
you will suffer
brain damage as well.
I understand.
( rumbling )
Take those two to the brig.
Captain, if we replay those
events and they see you,
it will disrupt
the memory again.
Then we've got
to find a way
to make me
inconspicuous.
All right, Gamma Shift,
time to defend the Federation
against gaseous anomalies.
( crew chuckling )
How are you, Ensign?
Who are you?
We could have
just asked her.
Asking female officers
for their clothing
could lead
to misunderstanding.
DOCTOR:
I've programmed
a cortical stimulator
to emit thoron radiation.
We'll bombard his
telepathic cortex.
That should be enough
to terminate the meld.
We'll begin with
a 20-kilodyne burst
of five-second
duration on my mark.
Now.
It's working.
Their neural patterns
are starting to separate.
( console beeps )
My god.
What is it?
That's Tuvok's
memory engram.
That's the Captain's.
But this red pattern
seems to be another engram.
A third memory engram.
How's that possible?
It's not--
which means it can't
really be an engram.
From the neurochemical
modulation,
I'd say it's something
masquerading as an engram.
The way viruses
sometimes mimic
certain blood
factors to avoid
being destroyed
by antibodies?
So you're saying
it's a virus.
I think so.
The thoron radiation
must have caused it
to manifest itself.
Increasing the radiation level
should destroy it.
Go to 40 kilodynes,
ten second burst.
Now!
The Klingon ship's
been disabled, sir.
They're no longer pursuing.
Helm, set a course
for Kronos.
Engage.
Who's at communications?
Commander Rand is supposed
to be on duty, sir.
Where is she?
Sir, long-range sensors
are detecting three
Klingon battle cruisers
on an intercept course.
They're arming torpedoes.
Maintain course.
Return fire!
VALTANE:
They've knocked out
our targeting scanners, sir.
SULU:
Switch to manual.
Mr. Valtane,
there's a rupture
in the plasma conduit
behind your console.
Get away from that station.
One more second.
Dmitri, you must...
( yelling )
It's about to happen.
Try to remember
every detail
about the next few seconds.
Concentrate.
Tuvok...
GIRL:
Help me!
Help me, Tuvok!
I saw her, Tuvok.
I saw the girl.
Stay with it.
( sighs )
I am trying.
But my mind is weakening.
This is our last chance.
Take us to the precipice.
Concentrate.
Take us to the girl.
DOCTOR:
It's working.
The mind-meld
is almost broken
and the radiation appears
to be killing the virus.
Increase thoron
levels to...
( console beeping )
The virus
is migrating.
It's embedding itself
in the Captain's brain.
Cortical stimulator.
GIRL:
Kathryn!
Help me, Kathryn, please!
Don't let go.
Don't let me fall!
No!
Program a 50-kilodyne burst
five-second duration
on my mark. Now.
Help me, Tuvok!
The virus protein structures
are breaking down.
It's dying.
Increase thoron radiation
to 80 kilodynes
15 seconds. Now.
GIRL:
Help me, Dmitri!
Please, don't let go!
Don't let me fall!
DOCTOR:
Again!
Don't let me fall!
No!
DOCTOR:
It's clearly a viral
parasite of some kind,
but its origin and
genome classification
are not on record.
We were able to kill it
using thoron radiation.
What do you know
about it?
The virus thrives
on peptides
generated in the brain.
It evades the body's
immune system
by disguising itself
as a memory engram.
Apparently,
the parasite used
the childhood memory
of the falling girl
as camouflage.
Creating a false
memory so traumatic
that the mind
would repress it
and that's where
it would live, in
person after person,
hiding in a part
of the brain
that the conscious mind
would want to avoid
at all costs.
When it sensed
the death of the host,
it would leave
to find another.
That's why it migrated
from Valtane to me.
KES:
What about the girl?
Did she ever really exist
or did the organism
invent the memory?
Memory is a tricky thing.
If it was a real event,
it's been buried and copied
and twisted so many times
there's no way to tell
what really happened.
Thank you, Doctor.
I'm curious.
Did the Excelsior ever
save Kirk and McCoy?
Not directly.
We were forced to retreat
back to Federation space.
As usual, Captain Kirk provided
his own means of escape.
But we did play
a pivotal role
at the subsequent battle
at Khitomer.
Mr. Tuvok, if I didn't
know you better,
I'd say you miss those
days on the Excelsior.
On the contrary.
I do not experience
feelings of nostalgia.
But there are times
when I think back
to those days
of meeting Kirk, Spock,
and the others,
and I am pleased
that I was part of it.
In a funny way,
I feel like I was
a part of it, too.
Then perhaps you can be
nostalgic for both of us.