MAN 1: New man coming!
( alarm blaring )
MAN 2: New prisoner!
Get out of my way!
MAN 3:
New man coming!
MAN 2:
Get out of my way!
( alarm blaring )
MAN 2: Here he comes!
Get ready! Let's go!
MAN 3:
Hurry up! They're gonna
push off! Let's go!
MAN 2:
New prisoner!
MAN 3: Hey! Something's
coming down there!
( grunts )
( prisoners clamoring )
Hey, get out of my...
( prisoners yelling )
( grunts )
( grunting )
Kill him! Kill him!
Tom.
( grunts )
( prisoners cheering )
( coughs )
( dramatic
theme music playing )
( groans softly )
Nobody touch him.
He's mine.
Wait. This is a mistake.
I don't belong here!
You don't?
Well, I'll just take
you home, then.
All right?
This one's mine.
I say he's not.
He's the reason
that I'm here.
He was my partner
in a bombing.
We killed 47 patrollers
on Akritiri-- 47!
And then this scum
confessed to the tribunal
and gave them my name.
So I'm telling you again,
he's mine.
I'm keeping him.
( sighs )
Take him.
For now.
KIM:
Did you have
to hit me so hard?
PARIS:
Trust me-- around here,
you don't want anybody
thinking you're soft.
Thanks for the tip.
Is there any food?
I haven't had anything
to eat since I got here.
How long is that?
A couple of days.
( scoffs )
Some shore leave, huh?
What happened to you
after they split us up?
The Akritirians
interrogated me.
When I wouldn't confess
to the bombing,
they dragged me
in front of a judge.
He said you'd already
confessed for the both of us,
and then
he pronounced me guilty.
That's exactly
what happened to me.
Then they must
have drugged me,
because the next
thing I knew,
I woke up at the
bottom of the chute
to that welcoming party.
We've got to explain
to somebody
that there's been
a mistake.
Who did you have in mind?
A guard.
The warden.
I haven't seen
anybody like that.
A prison without guards?
The other inmates say
this place is 300
meters underground.
Maybe the Akritirians figure
guards aren't necessary.
Can I have some more?
What do you think
this is?
A hotel?
There isn't any more!
Take it easy!
( sighs )
I'm sorry.
I'm... really
starting to get edgy.
I think it's the clamp.
The what?
That's what the prisoners
call it.
Everybody has one.
What is it?
I'm guessing it's some kind
of synaptic stimulator.
Anyway, it's affecting
my nervous system.
I've been getting jumpier
ever since I got here.
Not to mention,
this thing itches like crazy.
What do you think it's for?
Maybe it's some kind
of torture device.
We could try
taking them out.
No! I saw someone try it.
It killed him.
What we have to do
is find a way out
of this place.
Hm.
Let's get something
straight first.
What?
The next time you take
a swing at me,
I'm hitting back.
( alarm blaring )
What's that?
Another prisoner,
maybe?
PRISONER:
Food coming!
Food!
Join me for dinner?
( clamoring )
( screaming )
No! There's got
to be more!
( screams )
( groans )
I don't think he was going
to eat it anyway, do you?
He's dead.
I think I've lost
my appetite.
JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 50156.2.
After 72 hours,
Lieutenant Paris
and Ensign Kim
are still missing,
and I'm quickly
losing patience
with the Akritirian
authorities.
They continue to deny us
access to the surface,
and they've yet to confirm
whether our crewmen
were killed in the bombing.
Anything?
I have completed another
full sensor sweep,
including a multispectral
subsurface scan.
I still cannot locate
their life signs
or their combadges.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain,
Ambassador Liria
is hailing us.
On screen.
I'm only in the mood
for good news today, Ambassador.
LIRIA:
I'm afraid I can't oblige.
Are you saying
they're dead?
No, they're
very much alive.
Then where
are they?
Your men have been convicted
of the terrorist bombing
at the Laktivia recreational
facility, which resulted
in the death of 47
off-duty patrollers.
I assure you,
Ambassador,
my people had nothing to do
with this attack.
We found chemical traces
of the explosive used
in the bombing
on their hands and clothing.
I'm sure
the same could be said
of anyone who was near
the explosion.
It's hardly enough evidence
for a conviction.
The explosive
was trilithium based.
There is no source
of trilithium
anywhere in our system.
So, you can imagine
our surprise
when our investigation revealed
that your ship is powered
by dilithium--
which our scientists
tell us is convertible
into trilithium.
We have long suspected
that the so-called
Open Sky terrorists
had off-world collaborators.
Now we know who they are.
Captain, two Akritirian ships
are approaching
at bearing
271 mark 64.
Prepare your ship
for inspection, Captain.
If it will help confirm
our innocence, I'll consider it.
But first, I want to know
where my people are being held,
and I want to talk
to them immediately.
Communication with inmates
is not permitted.
If you want my cooperation,
Ambassador,
you're going to have
to do better than that.
Perhaps
you've misunderstood me.
Let me clarify our position.
Your vessel
is being impounded.
You and your crew
are under arrest.
Prepare to be boarded.
Captain, their ships
are powering weapons.
Mr. Tuvok, raise shields.
Mr. Chakotay, take the conn.
I'd like to resolve
this situation
peacefully, Ambassador,
but let me clarify my position.
I will not allow
this ship to be boarded.
That, Captain,
is an error in judgment.
( intense
dramatic score playing )
Captain, should I
return fire?
That's not going to help us
get Tom and Harry back.
We need to regroup.
Get us out of here, Commander.
CHAKOTAY:
Aye, Captain.
( soft chattering )
( footsteps approaching )
What took you so long?
I've been back
at least half an hour.
You're starting to
feel it, aren't you?
I guess I am.
It gets worse
all the time.
We have to fight it.
Let's focus on
something positive.
How about...
a seven-course dinner?
I suppose you didn't
find any food.
Well... I found close
to 50 good citizens
in this quaint
little community,
but not a grocer
among them.
I take it that's a no.
Yeah.
But if we ever do get
our hands on some food,
I found a lovely
spot for a picnic.
Great.
All we need
are the Delaney sisters,
and we could
make a day of it.
So, how about you?
Come across anything
interesting
in your travels?
If you mean an escape route,
I ran into nothing
but solid walls.
( sighs heavily )
Me, too.
As far as I can see,
the only way to the surface
is that chute
in the main chamber.
The question is:
How do we get into it
without getting fried
by that force field?
You saw what happened
to the man who reached inside.
That's where this
might come in handy.
I thought if
we could get
our hands on
some loose wiring,
you might be able to use it
to rig a device
that would short out
the force field,
long enough for us
to get into the tube.
It's worth a try.
Yeah.
Now, if we could only
figure out a way
to short out these implants,
we'd be all set.
There's no indication
they followed us.
I guess they're
more interested
in getting rid of us
than finding out the truth.
We've got to go back
for Harry and Tom.
B'Elanna...
We have no information
as to their whereabouts,
and if we return
to Akritirian space,
we are sure to encounter
further hostilities.
Tuvok is right.
Let's concentrate on
proving
Harry and Tom's innocence.
How do we do that?
We know the explosive
was trilithium-based.
If we find the source
of that trilithium,
it may lead us
to the real bombers.
Our long-range scans indicate
that Liria was right.
There's no trilithium
in this sector.
What about paralithium?
It's used as a fuel
for some ion-based
propulsion systems
and it can be converted
into trilithium.
Review our sensor logs
of ships entering and leaving
Akritirian space
during the time
we were in orbit.
If anybody's using
paralithium for fuel,
I want to find out
who they are
and where they went.
Come on, come on, come on...
Take it easy.
You'll get it.
( object clangs )
( breathing heavily )
( stamps foot )
I can't think!
I can't concentrate!
Okay, okay,
concentrate on this.
Uh... Um...
Crown roast of lamb
with, uh...
a bed of wild rice
and a 2296 Chateau
Lafite Rothschild...
at the real Sandrine's.
Or how about shrimp
with fettran sauce,
flambé noodles,
and fudge ripple pudding.
Good one.
Okay. Uh...
A couple of barbecued
T-bone steaks
with baked Risan beans
and... cherry pie
for dessert.
Let's see you
top that one.
Right now, I'm so hungry,
I could eat a bowl of
Neelix's leola root stew.
Me, too.
Never thought
I'd say that.
I'm ready to
give it a try.
So far, so good.
( grunts )
Are you okay?
What are you doing?
Just out for a
little stroll.
Move it!
What's that?
A pipe.
Let's see it.
Come on.
I'd really recommend
that you stay
out of my way.
Heh. You should have
thought of that
before you took him!
( clamoring )
Come on, Tom!
( grunts )
Tom!
( screaming )
Back off! Back off!
Hang on. I'm getting
you out of here.
No fight. No fight.
If he doesn't
bleed to death,
he'll die
from infection.
We've got to get him
to a doctor.
Of course. We'll call
an emergency vehicle
and rush him
to a hospital.
( prisoners laughing )
( groaning )
Hey!
What do you want
for the dead man's boots?
MAN 1: Nice!
MAN 2: I'll take
his shirt, too.
You can make it.
Just a few more steps,
and we'll be back
to the shelter.
Home, sweet home.
Harry.
Yeah?
I'm hurt pretty bad.
I'll take
care of it.
Promise me something.
What?
If things get worse...
if it comes down
to making a choice,
don't worry about me.
Take care of yourself.
Do we have a deal?
Quiet.
Hey!
What are you
doing in there?
Get out.
This place is ours.
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
( footsteps and groaning )
Okay, here's the deal.
My boots for
some clean cloth,
a liter of water,
two of those food cakes,
and my friend gets to stay
in there until he's better.
I don't take in boarders.
What about
the rest of it?
I don't like the color.
( sighs )
Come on, let's go.
This guy's not
going to help us.
Just tell me what you want
for the food
and the bandages, okay?
That pipe you were working with
interests me.
I can't trade the pipe.
Then I guess
we don't have a deal.
Now move on.
You're blocking my light.
I'll take you with me.
Take me where?
I know a way
out of this place.
I've been in here
six years.
I've never heard
of a way out.
The chute.
Anybody that tries
to get in there
gets hit with an energy pulse.
With this pipe,
I can disable the force field.
With a little luck,
we can make it to the surface.
What are you staring at?
I'm trying to figure out
if you're a liar...
or if the clamp has
already made you crazy.
Neither.
And I'll prove it to you.
You stand your ground.
I like that.
Then we have a deal?
Just remember one thing:
If you're lying,
I'll kill you.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
So far, we've located
three ships
with paralithium plasma
emissions,
but none of them appears
to have produced explosives.
We're currently in pursuit
of a fourth vessel.
We're in hailing range
of the Akritirian
freighter, Captain.
TUVOK:
I'm only reading
two life signs aboard.
Open a channel.
This is Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager
to the captain
of the Akritirian cargo vessel.
I'm the captain
of this vessel.
What do you want?
Two of my crew members
were convicted
by the Akritirians
of a terrorist bombing.
We're trying to prove
their innocence,
and we have reason to believe
a ship like yours,
which uses paralithium for fuel,
might have been involved
in the production
of the explosives.
( whispers )
Let's get out of here.
Quiet.
This is a cargo vessel.
Then you won't mind
if a few of my crew members
come aboard to have
a look around.
Not if they don't mind
having their throats cut.
JANEWAY: There's no need
to be abrupt...
I guess you're not
the only captain
who doesn't want
their ship boarded.
TORRES: Captain,
I'm picking up
residual traces
of trilithium.
They're faint,
but they're there.
I think we may have found
our bomb makers.
Mr. Tuvok, send
a security detail
to Transporter Room 2.
Lieutenant Torres,
beam the two of them aboard
and tractor their ship
into the shuttle bay.
Aye, Captain.
You have no right
to hold us.
My people
have been accused
of aiding a terrorist group
called Open Sky.
What do you
know about them?
They're not
terrorists.
They're patriots.
One day, they'll lead
the legitimate government
of our people.
We don't have
to answer any of
their questions, Piri.
It sounds to me
like your young friend here
sympathizes
with these patriots.
She's not
my friend.
She's my sister.
And our political views
are none of your business.
I don't know much
about your world,
but I do know that my people
are being held
for a crime they didn't commit,
and I'm going to do everything
in my power to get them out.
Do you understand that?
We have confirmed
that explosives
were indeed produced
aboard their ship.
Escort them to the brig.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
And have Mr. Chakotay
lay in a course
for the Akritirian border.
Let my
sister go.
She didn't have anything
to do with the bombing,
and she's only 14.
Prison doesn't
scare me.
Quiet, Piri.
Please.
You don't know
what you're saying.
Nobody ever gets out
of prison on Akritiri.
They'll just let
her rot in there
for the rest of her life.
I admire your desire
to protect your sister, but...
it's not really
up to me, is it?
Tell them
what we know.
Tell me what?
Piri, don't.
Our brigade found out
where the maximum security
detention facility is located.
My sister has quite
a vivid imagination.
With this ship,
you can attack the prison
and get your
people out.
I'm sorry,
that's not how we do things
where I come from.
Coward.
Mr. Tuvok,
see that they get a bath
and a hot meal.
I don't trust
that guy, Harry.
I can handle him.
Just watch
your back, okay?
Try to get some rest.
Remember our deal?
What deal?
If it comes down to it,
you're going to save
yourself, right?
If you see a chance,
just go.
Don't come back for me.
I think the clamp
must really be starting
to make you crazy.
I'm serious, Harry.
Getting tired
of waiting.
I gotta go.
Harry...
Oh! Damn it!
Don't fight it, use it.
How do I do that?
I feel like there's
a million fire ants
in my brain.
Good. Make them
work for you.
How?
Fire ants sound vicious.
Imagine them as your army
moving in a vast wave
to conquer your enemy.
There's a massive struggle
going on inside you--
a battle to the death
between you and the clamp.
You have to use whatever force
you can to defeat it.
I'd rather
use my energy
to work on getting
out of here.
When I first got here,
I assumed the clamp
was just a refined form
of torture
to make our prison stay
that much more arduous.
Gradually, I began
to understand it more fully.
It's all right here
in my manifesto--
my insights, my reasoning...
My evidence.
It's an experiment.
They're studying us
like animals--
pitting us against each other
to find out what happens.
You can see that,
can't you?
I guess so.
The greatest threat,
of course, would be
if we started to cooperate
with each other,
so they prevented that.
But there had to be
more to it than that,
and the longer I was in here,
the more I knew it was my job
to figure it out.
That's the reason
I was put here,
and eventually...
it came to me
as though a fireball
had exploded in my mind.
And the realization gave me
a power over the others.
They don't come
near me anymore.
They're afraid of me,
because I know the truth.
Well...?
Don't you want to know
what it is?
What is the ultimate purpose
of the clamp?
Okay.
It's inspired,
brilliant.
It's a method for controlling
the prison population.
We kill each other off.
Sure. Whatever you say.
So you must enter
into the battle.
If you let the clamp
control you,
you'll end up
like that crazy old man
that took over your shelter.
But if you learn
to control it,
you'll survive...
like me.
( beeping )
Yes.
I plan to be out of here
before it even
becomes an issue.
Go ahead.
Touch it.
( grunting )
What do you see?
Some kind of hatch.
Are we
at the surface?
Heh. Harry.
How are you feeling?
I was dreaming...
about Megan Delaney.
( laughs )
Next time,
I'll try not to wake you.
The chute...
You made it in?
Did you
find a way out?
Not yet...
but we're very close.
It's just a matter of time.
So you've got
to hang in there, okay?
Wh... Wha...
What happened to me?
Easy, Tom.
You got stabbed, remember?
Who...
Who did it?
One of the prisoners.
No...
No, it was you!
I'm trying
to change your bandage.
No! Get away from me!
Please! I'm trying
to help you.
Get away from me!
Tom!
Tom, give me the pipe.
We need it to get out of here.
Remember?
It's okay.
Let me take it.
Harry...
What's happening to me?
You're gonna be okay.
Harry...
Yeah?
Don't leave me here.
Close your eyes.
( prisoners hooting, shouting
and laughing maniacally )
( shouting and wild laughter
continues )
Sleep well?
No.
How about
your friend?
Is he dead yet?
Shut up!
The chute leads
to a docking port, right?
Some kind of ship must come
to drop off food,
drop off new prisoners.
So maybe we could
get aboard the ship.
It's getting
the best of you.
I know we could do it.
You think they're just
gonna open the hatch
and ask us if we'd
like a ride home?
We'd have
the element of surprise.
And they'd have
the pulse guns.
If we could hold them off...
distract them...
just for a few minutes...
I could
establish our location...
MAN:
That's enough!
...get a message to Voyager
and they could
get us out of here.
We'll need weapons.
I've never
let anyone see this,
but I'm going to let
you read my manifesto.
It'll teach you
how to control the clamp.
I don't want to read
your crazy manifesto.
Take it.
Learn everything
I know.
Now, are you going
to help me or not?
If I were like
the others...
I'd kill you.
But I don't lose control.
That's the difference
between me
and you.
Listen!
Listen to me, everybody!
MAN: Now what's he want?
This is important.
I've got something to say.
Something you want to hear.
It's what you've
been waiting for.
What the hell
do you want?
I've found a way
out of here.
( laughter and shouting )
There's no way out.
There is!
Through the chute!
I've been inside.
( grunts )
Listen!
We have to work together.
They'd like us all
to kill each other,
but we have to cooperate.
If we do,
we can get out of here.
If you've been in the chute,
where does it lead?
MAN:
Yeah! Yeah!
Space.
( derisive shouts and laughter )
It's the truth.
We can escape...
if we work together!
( grunts )
What the hell
are you doing?
Stay back.
You've ruined it.
This is mine.
It's mine!
( screaming )
Please! No!
Please!
Harry!
No!
( screaming )
Go ahead.
Finish him.
You wanted to kill him,
didn't you?
He's my best friend!
No, no, that's
where you're wrong.
He's too far gone
to be your friend.
All he is now is a burden.
That's not true!
He eats your food,
he ruined your device--
he's given in
to the clamp.
You've got to get rid of him
before he brings you
down with him.
Quiet!
You've got a chance
to make something
of your life in here,
but as long as that carcass
is in my hut,
we'll never be able to go on
to more important things.
What the hell are
you talking about?
We've got to disseminate
the manifesto,
gather our followers,
train them.
You're insane.
You want my protection?
You want to live
under my roof?
Get rid of him.
I don't need
your protection!
How long do you
think you'll last
against Pit
and the others,
without me
looking out for you?
Go ahead. Take it.
Think of what
a relief it will be
to not have
that responsibility,
to be free
of his ranting.
I'm not a killer.
If you want
to survive in here...
you'd better learn to be.
If that's what it takes
to stay alive...
then I'd rather die.
( shank clangs )
Get out now.
And take him with you...
or I will kill him.
Unless you've decided
to relinquish control
of your vessel, Captain,
I suggest that you do not
proceed across our border.
We've captured
the ship and crew
responsible for the bombing
at the Laktivia Canteen.
I see...
I'm prepared to trade them
for the immediate
and unconditional release
of Lieutenant Paris
and Ensign Kim.
Your crewmen have already
been tried and convicted.
Are you saying those
convictions can't be reversed,
no matter what new evidence
is brought to light?
You are correct.
That is an outrageous policy.
I assure you, it has proved to
be a most effective deterrent.
Good day, Captain.
( sighs in disgust )
So much for negotiating.
What should we do
with the prisoners?
Bring Vel
to my ready room. Now.
I want the location
and shield code
to the maximum security
detention facility.
What's wrong,
the Akritirians didn't
agree to your terms?
No, as a matter of fact.
But I suspect you will.
And what makes you so sure?
Because if you don't,
you and your sister
are going to spend the rest
of your lives in prison.
I'll take you
to the prison,
and I'll get you in,
but there are members
of Open Sky in there
and I want to
get them out, too.
I don't think you understand
the way this works.
You tell me
what I want to know,
and after I get my people back,
I let you and your sister go.
That's not good enough.
Mr. Tuvok, inform
the Akritirians
that we're ready
to turn the prisoners over.
( scoffs )
All right.
TUVOK:
Crewman Foster,
take the prisoner
to Commander Chakotay.
He will upload
the coordinates and codes.
May I ask how you propose
to get past the
Akritirian patrols?
No doubt they will attack
as soon as Voyager
crosses the border.
That's exactly why
the rescue team
won't be aboard Voyager.
Captain?
If I'm not mistaken,
Mr. Neelix's ship
is still in our shuttle bay.
Yes.
However,
Mr. Neelix's vessel
has extremely limited
combat capabilities.
Then we'll have to be
very careful, won't we?
PIT:
I want his clothes
and I want his shoes!
This man is my friend.
Nobody touches him.
Back off! You won't
have to get hurt.
( alarm blaring )
New prisoner!
( inmates clamoring )
I got her!
Hands on your heads.
Do it now!
NEELIX [OVER INTERCOM]:
Neelix to Lieutenant Tuvok.
Go ahead.
We've got company.
Two Akritirian patrol ships
on an intercept course.
I'm not sure how long
I can hold them off.
TUVOK: We are moving as quickly
as we can, Mr. Neelix.
KIM:
Captain!
Where's Tom?
He needs help.
MALE ALIEN: Akritirian patrol
to alien vessel.
Disengage immediately.
Akritirian patrol?
Uh, am I in Akritirian space?
Oh, dear.
I-I thought this was
the Heva VII refueling port.
Uh, you wouldn't, by any chance,
be able to recommend a...
respectable establishment
where I could have
my navigational array repaired?
Disengage immediately.
This is your final warning.
JANEWAY: Janeway to Neelix.
Everyone's aboard.
Acknowledged.
I know it's a little
cramped back there,
so if there's anything I can do
to make you more comfortable...
Neelix!
Just get us out of here!
Of course, Captain.
Talaxian vessel
to Akritirian patrol.
My apologies
for the little mix-up.
I'll be departing now,
per your orders.
Power down your engines
and prepare to be boarded.
Eh, what was that, patrol?
That last message was garbled.
( rumbling from phaser strikes )
NEELIX: I've always thought
of my piloting skills
as modest, at best,
and the conditions
were extremely dangerous.
Still, I did outmaneuver
those Akritirians, didn't I?
You did a terrific
job, Neelix.
I agree.
Excellent piloting.
I'm glad to hear you
say that, Captain,
because I've been thinking...
Until Tom here
gets back on his feet,
perhaps I could try my hand
at conn for a while.
That won't
be necessary.
Lieutenant Paris
is just fine,
thanks to excellent
doctoring.
I finished analyzing
these implants,
and you'll be happy
to know that the treatment
I provided will
successfully
counteract their
effect on you.
What exactly
was the effect?
My readings indicate
that the implants
are designed
to stimulate the production
of acetylcholine
in the hypothalamus.
That would explain
the agitation.
Hm. Acetylcholine
is a brain chemical
common to the neural
structures of most humanoids.
Essentially,
it helps stimulate
one's aggressive
tendencies.
Zio was right.
( sighs )
Come on, Harry.
We're overdue
for that steak dinner.
I guess so.
What do you mean,
you guess so?
It's the thought
of that dinner
that kept us going.
So what
do you think?
Uh, a baked potato?
A big mound of
deep-fried onion rings?
Tom...
Maybe, maybe, uh...
some grilled mushrooms.
Tom, listen to me.
I...
I almost killed you.
What are you saying?
You're the one
that kept me alive.
I was ready to hit
you with the pipe.
Don't you remember?
You want to know
what I remember?
Someone saying,
"This man is my friend.
Nobody touches him."
I'll remember that
for a long time.
So, what do you say
we blow
a week's worth
of replicator rations?
So, what's for dessert?
Cherry pie,
don't you remember?
What about the fudge
ripple pudding?
Ah! Yes...
( dramatic
theme music playing )