PARIS:
Helmsman's Log,
Stardate 50252.3.
While Voyager
takes on supplies,
Lieutenant Torres and I
are investigating
some intermittent
sensor readings
we picked up this morning.
( sighs )
We've been out here
almost five hours
and we haven't seen any sign
of those energy signatures.
Isn't it time to admit
they were nothing more
than galactic
background noise?
I want to keep looking
a while longer.
Just to be sure.
Aah!
What's wrong?
Cramp.
Klingon bodies weren't meant
to sit in a cockpit
for five hours
at a stretch.
You have a big dinner
date or something?
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, you've been angling
to get back to Voyager
for about two hours now.
Just thought maybe
there was a reason.
Like Ensign Bristow.
What?
Well, I've noticed he's
been making any excuse
to hang around Engineering.
Around you.
Freddy Bristow... is a child.
Oh, really?
Well, he looks like
a grownup to me.
Tall, good-looking...
and I hear he plays
a mean set
of parrises squares.
I played one game with him
and I whipped him.
Look, he has
a crush on me.
I can handle it.
Why are you so interested?
Oh, I'm just curious...
how someone with Klingon blood
seems to live the life
of a Tabran monk.
Lieutenant, that is none
of your business.
Well, if you ever have
a free evening,
I have a holodeck program
you might enjoy--
sailing on Lake Como.
I'd rather take my chances
with Freddy Bristow.
( console beeps )
Those energy signatures
are back.
We must have crossed
into a tachyon field.
( console beeps insistently )
What's that?
A ship has locked
onto our hull.
Why didn't we
detect it?
The tachyon field must have
disrupted our sensors.
( speaking clicking language )
I'm Lieutenant Tom Paris of...
( both grunt )
( clicking )
MAN:
♪ O soave fanciulla ♪
♪ O dolce viso ♪
♪ Di mite circonfuso
alba lunar ♪
♪ In terra, vivo ravviso ♪
♪ Il sogno ch'io
vorrei sempre sognar ♪
♪ Fremon... già nell'anima ♪
♪ Le dolcezze estreme ♪
♪ Tu sol commandi, amore... ♪
Computer,
pause playback.
Excuse me, but your
entrance was early.
You're rushing
the tempo.
( chuckles )
I am not rushing.
You are lagging behind
like a tired donkey.
I assure you,
I have studied
the finest recordings
of this opera--
Caruso and Galli-Curci;
Pavarotti and Freni;
Soral and T'Penna
of Vulcan.
My tempo is accurate.
Galli-Curci... Freni...
T'Penna... they are all fallite.
They are mere dust balls.
Sono niente!
They are nothing.
Giuseppina Pentangeli--
the greatest soprano lirico
of the 22nd century
transcends them all.
And conductors take
their tempi from me.
Capisci?
In this instance,
they take it from me.
I've programmed
the orchestral playback.
Who allows you
to make this choice?
You are an amateur.
You have no sense of rubato,
no rallentando...
it's like
singing with a computer.
Madam, I may be an amateur,
but I'm also known
as a quick study.
( laughing )
And as I am in charge of this
program, you will do it my way.
Shall we
try it again?
Computer,
start playback.
( opera music playing )
♪ O soave fanciulla ♪
♪ O... ♪
Stop playback.
( sighs )
What now?
Non è possibile.
I couldn't remember
the words.
In all of my career, I have
never forgotten the lyrics.
This is the difference
between amateur
and professionali.
Just a momentary lapse.
No need to overreact.
Piu cretino non esiste.
This is infuriating!
I want another partner!
Lo voglio subito.
I'm the one who needs
another partner.
You've got me so upset
I can't sing.
Computer, delete...
Janeway to the Doctor.
We have a medical emergency.
Report to Sick Bay.
Right away, Captain.
Addio, madam.
Next time I'll take
my chances with Maria Callas.
Computer,
delete the diva.
Imbecille!
Pensa veramente...
Their nervous systems
suffered trauma
from some type
of neuroelectric weapon.
It must have been
extremely painful.
It certainly was.
Do you know why
they attacked you?
No idea. They seemed to be
trying to communicate with us,
but we couldn't
understand them.
Then they just
lifted their weapons.
The injuries are treatable.
It shouldn't take long.
Tuvok, send a message
on all subspace bands.
I want to find out why
my people were attacked.
Aye, Captain.
I'll ask Neelix if he knows
anything about these people.
Doctor, keep me posted.
( sighs )
It would help if you
didn't fidget so much.
I'm really feeling better.
Can't I get out of here?
When you're ready to leave,
I will tell you.
KES:
Doctor,
Tom doesn't seem to be
responding to the treatment.
I'll look at him.
Where's my retinal imager?
I haven't seen it.
Did you move it
from the instrument tray?
I haven't been near
the instrument tray.
I've just had
the most unpleasant encounter
with a madwoman
on the holodeck.
She must have upset me
more than I realized.
Lieutenant, you're perfectly
all right.
What are you
still doing here?
Thank you.
I think he must have suffered
some very deep tissue damage.
The regenerator
isn't helping.
Doctor?
Hmm?
I've made numerous hails
on wide-band subspace.
The only response has been
a single repeating message.
( clicking )
CHAKOTAY:
What's that?
I'd guess
it's a language so unlike ours
that the universal translator
can't interpret it.
Harry, remodulate
the translator.
See if we can
decipher those sounds.
Neelix, what can you tell us?
If these people are
who I think they are,
I can tell you this
is very bad news.
I've never actually
encountered them...
but from what I've heard,
I'm glad I didn't.
Most ships
that enter their space
are never heard from again.
Some have returned with
everyone on board dead.
They're a complete mystery.
No one knows their name,
how many of them there are,
what their culture is like.
Just that they really
don't want people
violating their territory.
If this is any indication
of their borders,
it's a huge area of space--
hundreds of sectors.
If we were to go around it,
it would take months.
I'd say over 15 months,
even if we could sustain
maximum warp, which we can't.
I'm not going to tell this crew
we're adding another 15 months
to this journey.
We'll have to find
another option.
If we are not to go around
their space,
the only available option
is to go through it.
Precisely.
KIM:
Tom and B'Elanna
hit a sensor net
as they crossed the border.
We have to figure we'll run
into it when we try to cross,
but there are ways
around sensor nets.
CHAKOTAY:
They can't possibly
have enough ships
to patrol a border this size.
We can probably find
an unguarded section.
Would it affect your decision
if I pointed out
that encroaching on the
territory of an alien species
is prohibited by
Starfleet regulations?
No, it wouldn't.
Captain... you have managed
to surprise me.
We're a long way
from Starfleet, Lieutenant.
I'm not about to waste
15 months
because we've run into
a bunch of bullies.
DOCTOR:
Sick Bay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Doctor.
Please turn to your emergency
medical holographic channel.
I'm afraid Lieutenant Paris
suffered greater
neurological damage
than my initial scan revealed.
I'm going to have to perform
a motor cortex reconstruction.
There's no need
to be overly concerned.
His condition
is not life threatening.
The procedure is
a relatively simple one
for a skilled physician.
Very good, Doctor.
Keep me informed.
All right. I want a plan
for crossing that border
as quickly
and as quietly as possible.
We'll reconvene in an hour.
Dismissed.
♪ O soave fanciulla ♪
♪ O dolce viso ♪
♪ Di mite circonfuso
alba lunar... ♪
Doctor...
I have the cortical
analeptics you asked for.
Good.
Fill the hyposprays.
We'll begin as soon as
I've finished scrubbing.
Did I hear
you singing?
Yes.
"O soave fanciulla."
It's an aria
from La Bohème,
a truly exquisite opera
by Giacomo Puccini,
a human composer
of the 19th century.
I didn't realize
you enjoyed music.
I've recently begun
a thorough study of opera.
I find it...
quite satisfying,
but I'm having
difficulty finding
a holographic partner
for the role of Mimi.
All the soprani seem to have
the most
irritating personalities.
These women are arrogant,
superior, condescending.
I can't imagine anyone
behaving that way.
What is it?
A quiz for you.
What is the first step
in this procedure?
Establish
the axon connections
and then test
for synaptic potentials.
Ah. Quite right. Very good.
Doctor, what is it?
We seem to have
a small problem.
I... can't remember how to
perform this operation.
All right, I've
repaired the damaged
preganglionic fibers
in the spinal column.
The final step
is to restore the nerve sheath.
You'll need
the myelin regenerator.
( alarm beeping )
What is it?
He's going
into respiratory arrest.
What do I do?
Apply an efferent impulse
to stabilize his motor neurons.
Apply a... what?
Vital signs are
returning to normal.
( sighs )
There-- myelin
regeneration is complete.
What's the synaptic
potential reading?
Synaptic
potentials are...
normal.
Autonomic and somatic
systems are functioning.
( sighs )
Very good, Doctor.
I think you've done it.
The EMH database
seems to be experiencing
a cascading overload
of some kind.
Doc's memory circuits
are deteriorating.
We knew the Doctor
was never designed
to be up and running
as much as he has been,
but I thought you programmed
safety buffers,
so his circuits
wouldn't degrade.
I did, and I installed
them, but they're
breaking down.
My self-diagnostic routines
have always indicated
that in the event
of cascade failure,
I should simply
be reinitialized.
That would stop the cascade
and allow us to reset
your database and personality
subroutines, but...
But what?
It would restore
the original program--
reset him to the person he was
when we first
activated him.
JANEWAY:
In other words,
he'd forget everything
that's happened to him
over the past two years.
TORRES:
Right.
Doctor...
how do you feel about that?
I... can't say I'd like
to lose the last two years,
but my primary responsibility
is the health and welfare
of this crew. In my current
state, I am useless to them.
I believe Lieutenant Torres
should start
the reinitialization
process immediately.
KES:
No, wait.
Wait, please.
We can't just treat the Doctor
like he's a computer anymore.
He's come too far
for that.
Doctor, please,
think about this.
You'd be losing so much--
all the relationships
you've developed,
our friendship,
your sense of being
a true member of this crew--
all that would be gone.
I can't put personal concerns
over those of the crew.
Look at the experiences
you've had
since you were activated--
you've made friends,
learned how to sing opera,
you've even
fallen in love.
If you lose those memories,
you won't be the same person.
You said you don't know
what's causing
his memory circuits to fail.
Unfortunately, no.
So, if you reinitialize without
finding out what's wrong,
the problem could occur again.
Well, it's a possibility.
Isn't it a better plan to look
for the cause of the problem?
If B'Elanna can find it,
there may be a less
radical solution.
Tom Paris is stable.
He'll be back on duty today.
There's no medical crisis
at the moment.
I can certainly handle
all the routine cases
in Sick Bay.
Please, let's not
just erase him
without trying
to help him first.
If a crew member came down
with a debilitating illness,
you'd do everything
in your power
to make them well again.
I think we owe you
nothing less.
I'll get started.
Don't be discouraged.
I know B'Elanna
can find a way.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain?
I think we found it--
a way to get across the border
without being detected.
Let's hear it.
Their sensor net
uses a series
of interlaced
tachyon beams.
If we adjust the shields
to refract those beams
around the ship,
we can slip across
without appearing
to have disrupted the net.
Not bad.
And we've found
that this area
shows no indication of vessels.
We can slide through,
go to high warp,
and be through this narrow
section of their territory
in four days.
Good work.
Helm, set a course
for the border.
Aye, Captain.
What are you
doing now?
I want to see
if the data corruption
is affecting
your optical sensors.
What did that do?
( gasps )
I-I can't see.
I'm blind!
All right.
( sighs )
That is extremely disconcerting.
Please don't
do it again.
Now what are you doing?
Attenuating your
force field projectors.
Doctor, forgive me,
but this is
very delicate work.
Could you please sit
over there for a few minutes?
How extremely rude.
May I remind you
that I am, in a way,
your patient, who's
suffering from an unknown
and obviously
debilitating condition.
I would think you'd be a little
more sensitive to my needs.
You're questioning
my bedside manner?
The good news
is that your
projection system
doesn't seem
to be affected.
However, I don't know why
your circuits are degrading.
Then... what do we do now?
What we do now...
is get a second opinion.
I'll transfer you to the
holodeck in a few minutes.
Wait here.
Computer, initiate
Jupiter Station
Diagnostic Program Alpha 1-1.
COMPUTER:
The program is activated.
Computer...
transfer the program
for the Emergency Medical
Hologram to Holodeck 2.
I seem to remember
this place.
You should--
this is Jupiter Station,
where you were created
and where your
database was written.
It seems... so long ago.
This program contains
a sophisticated
diagnostic matrix
specifically created
for the Emergency
Medical System.
That's right.
I should have
remembered that.
How could I
have forgotten?
I'm going to have to play with
the systems for a few minutes.
I'm not exactly sure how to
access all the subroutines.
Don't touch that!
( sighs )
Who are you?
I'm a holographic
re-creation
of Dr. Lewis Zimmerman,
the creator of the Emergency
Medical Hologram.
You're the
diagnostic matrix.
You might say that.
Something wrong with your EMH?
Yes.
I certainly hope
you're going to be able
to do something
about this annoying problem.
What's wrong with it?
He's experiencing
a cascade failure.
His memory circuits
are degrading.
I was trying to bring
the subroutines on line...
If you don't mind,
I can do it faster.
I can see where you get
your charming personality.
Not to mention
my hairline.
Here we are--
a schematic of the EMH
and its component subroutines.
Can you determine
the source of the problem?
This isn't good.
The EMH has a level-4
memory fragmentation.
How long has the program
been active?
I have been active
for...
Almost two years.
Two years?!
Well, there's your problem.
This program
was developed
as a short-term
supplement
to your medical staff--
1,500 hours tops.
I know.
I added data compression buffers
to compensate
for the additional time,
but they're breaking down.
The EMH is a highly
sophisticated program.
You shouldn't go meddling
in its matrix when you
don't know what
you're doing.
Should we shut down
his program then,
till we figure out
how to fix him?
At this point,
it doesn't matter.
With a level-4
memory fragmentation,
it'll simply continue
to degrade.
There's only one
course of action--
a system-wide reinitialization.
Start over from scratch.
We are aware of that option.
Would it be possible to expand
his memory circuits
instead?
Of course.
Schedule it for your next
maintenance layover
at McKinley Station.
I'm afraid that isn't possible.
We're thousands of light-years
from Federation space.
Well, there's
nothing more I can do.
Either reinitialize it,
or live with the knowledge
that eventually
this EMH will end up
with the intellectual
capacity of a parsnip.
What are you saying?
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Torres.
I'm here, Captain.
We're approaching the border.
We need your help
in Engineering.
I'm on my way.
Doctor-- Zimmerman--
you haven't told us anything
that we don't already know.
What I need is to find out
exactly why the Doctor's
memory circuits are degrading
so that we can come up
with a solution.
Activate a level-4 diagnostic,
or whatever you need to do
to get us some answers.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I... I wish you
didn't have to go.
( sighing )
I'll hurry.
I promise.
We're holding position
500,000 kilometers
from the border.
I'm ready to go as soon
as you give the word, Captain.
All set, Mr. Kim?
I'm ready whenever
Lieutenant Torres is.
Bridge to Engineering.
Torres here.
B'Elanna, are you ready
to reconfigure the shields
to match Mr. Kim's
refraction pulse?
Ready.
Captain, long-range sensors
show a large vessel
five light-years
from our current position.
PARIS:
According to my readings,
it's huge.
JANEWAY:
On screen.
Magnify.
That looks like
thousands of ships.
I'm not reading
any energy signatures.
Their propulsion systems
must be off-line.
Maybe they
haven't detected us.
Yet.
All right. Let's get through
that sensor net. Harry, go.
Engineering, initiate
the refraction pulse.
Pulse is activated.
Moving to full harmonic
resolution-- 60 percent.
80 percent.
Ninety...
Maximum resolution.
Shields at nominal output.
Mr. Paris, take us through.
Aye, sir.
Here we go.
The net is registering
as intact.
If those vessels get
the same readings,
they won't
suspect a thing.
( console beeps )
I think we did it, Captain.
Like a snake through the tube.
How about those ships?
They appear
not to have detected us.
They have not
powered up engines.
All right.
Let's get through this
as fast as we can.
Mr. Paris, what's
your recommendation?
I'll try holding
warp 9.75
for as long as I can.
If we can sustain that
for 12 hours,
we'll be nearly
a third of the way through.
Mr. Tuvok, keep your eye
on those ships.
If they so much as twitch,
I want to know it.
Captain...
something... is wrong.
What do you mean?
It's like there's a
drag on the engines.
Captain, sensors indicate
a resonant particle wave.
It's damping our warp field.
We're losing speed.
Bridge to Engineering.
B'Elanna, can you compensate
for the particle wave?
I'll try.
The antimatter reaction chamber
may have been compromised.
Keep me posted.
Hold our present speed,
Mr. Paris.
Why are you making me
stare at these things?
Please don't talk.
Stay fixed on
the fractal patterns
while I analyze your
data-path integrity.
Hmm...
Hmm?
Ew.
Well, there it is.
What? What is it?
I told you not to talk.
( sighing )
This is the problem, all right.
The personality subroutine
has grown to more
than 15,000 gigaquads.
That's the source
of the degradation.
Look at all this useless
information floating around
your buffer--
friendships with the crew,
relationships with...
women?
Do they find you attractive?
I don't remember.
You've filled your memory
with nonsense.
It was only during my off hours.
You're supposed to be off
during your off hours.
I'm sorry.
I... I didn't realize.
( door opening )
Who are you?
I'm the Doctor's assistant.
I came to see
how he's doing.
Ah, just the person I need.
Perhaps you can tell me
who's been feeding
all this useless information
into its database.
What do you mean?
I'll give you an example.
Ah! Here's something
in its
personality subroutine.
♪ O soave fanciulla ♪
♪ O... ♪
He's been studying opera.
What's wrong with that?
It wasn't programmed
to be a tenor,
it was programmed
to be a physician.
What's wrong with wanting
to be more than that?
It's superfluous.
Look at me.
I've got the same matrix,
the same holo-array,
the same neural pathways
as it does.
You don't see me
cluttering up my circuits
with irrelevancies.
I'm content to be
the best possible
diagnostic program I can be.
Your EMH should be happy
to be a fine physician.
The Doctor has taken it
upon himself
to become a person who grows
and learns and feels.
It's made him
a better physician.
An EMH program
can't feel anything.
It's emotional reactions are
simply a series of algorithms
designed to make it
easier to interact with.
He's much more than that,
and I've known him
for most of my life.
He's one of my closest friends.
You can't possibly believe
that this program
shares these feelings.
I know he does.
Tell me, Doctor, is this
one of your closest friends?
Doctor?
I'm sorry.
I don't know who you are.
What's the status
of those ships, Mr. Tuvok?
Still unpowered.
They don't seem to have
detected us.
When I was in high school,
I snuck out of the house
a couple of times late at night.
I had to tiptoe past
my parents' bedroom.
That's kind of how I feel
right now.
You sneaked out of your house?
Where were you going?
Well, I'll have to leave that
to your imagination,
Lieutenant.
Can I take a few guesses?
Captain, I'm detecting another
ship, not part of the swarm.
It has been damaged.
Propulsion systems
are not functional.
Drop out of warp.
Put it on screen.
PARIS:
Looks like it's
been pounded on for days.
Any life signs?
KIM:
I'm checking.
Only one, and it's faint.
Transporter Room 1,
beam the survivor to Sick Bay.
Harry, start scanning that ship.
See if you can figure out
what happened to it.
Aye, Captain.
He's suffering
from severe dehydration,
damage to the spinal column.
There's evidence
of trauma to the
nervous system,
just like we found
in B'Elanna and Tom
after they were attacked.
Can I talk to him?
You can try.
I'll work on restoring
his cranial nerves,
but he's so badly injured
I'm not sure it'll help.
He's a sick man.
This is where
sick people come.
Doctor, hold onto
this tricorder,
all right?
Keep it pointed
right at the patient.
I'm Kathryn Janeway,
the Captain of this ship.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Can you tell me
what happened?
Who attacked you?
There were
thousands of them.
Little ships...
swarmed around
my freighter.
Covered every square meter
of the hull.
Then they began
extracting energy
from all the ship's systems.
We had no defense.
Then they boarded us.
Did they use
neuroelectric weapons?
I don't know
what they used.
It was painful.
People screaming...
dying.
Had you... provoked them
in any way?
We were in their space.
That was enough.
Captain,
the rest of my crew...
is there anyone else?
I'm sorry.
You're the only survivor.
This woman is trying to
regenerate your motor neurons.
We come from Mislen...
five parsecs from here
in a yellow dwarf system.
If you pass,
will you tell our people?
I'll make a point of it.
It happened so quickly...
( steady tone sounds )
His injuries
were too severe.
He's a very sick man.
Captain, the Doctor
is getting worse.
He doesn't even know
who I am anymore.
He has to be
reinitialized.
I agree, but I can't
spare B'Elanna now.
We have to get
through this space
before we're attacked
like his ship was.
As soon as it's possible,
I'll break her free.
Is there anything at
all I can do for him?
The only thing
I can think of
is to keep his
neural pathways active.
Ask him questions.
Keep him thinking.
Force him to use
his neural matrix.
That might at least
slow down the degradation.
Doctor,
you mustn't touch those.
Here. This one's
all right to hold.
Shall I use it
on the sick man?
Yes, that's a good idea.
( instrument whirs )
The pilot of the freighter died.
We should keep going.
Mr. Paris...
Captain.
I am detecting a vessel.
It's one of the swarm.
PARIS:
It was still attached
to the freighter's hull.
Red Alert.
Shields at maximum.
They are scanning us,
Captain.
Hail them.
I am getting a response.
Audio only.
( alien language )
Harry, how are you coming
with the universal translator?
I'm working on it.
Let's see if they might
be able to understand us.
TUVOK:
Channel is open.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
We only want
to proceed peacefully
through this region of space.
( clicking )
Do you think they're trying
to communicate?
Could be, but what they're
trying to communicate
is another question.
Any progress, Harry?
I'm getting a general idea.
It's something
like... "Too late.
Should have listened."
Report.
We've been hit with some
kind of polaron burst.
TUVOK:
The energy expenditure
was not high enough
to cause any damage.
It may not have been a weapon.
Captain, that little ship
is hightailing it out of here.
So it scanned us,
sent out a polaron burst
that caused no damage,
and then took off.
Captain, the burst has
changed the shield polarity.
It's now rotating
at 92 gigahertz.
That means if anybody
wanted to find us,
it's a lot easier now.
I'll say. As far as anyone's
sensors are concerned,
we're lit up like
a Christmas tree.
TUVOK:
Captain, the
swarm of ships
has powered their engines
and turned toward us.
They are in pursuit.
Do what you can, Tom.
We have a head start.
We might be able to outrun them.
Bridge to Engineering.
Torres here.
How are you coming with
the warp drive, B'Elanna?
I'm going to try realigning
the dilithium matrix,
but we'll need to shut down
the warp drive to do it.
We can't shut down.
The alien ships
are headed toward us.
I don't know if I can do this
on the run, Captain,
but I'll give it a try.
Do the best you can.
Janeway out.
Nicoletti, we're going to
have to try
a dilithium realignment
on the fly.
Let's figure out
how to do it
without killing everyone
in Engineering.
I fail to understand
why I can't leave this room.
Stand aside, young woman, or
I will have you put on report.
Doctor, please, I'm just
trying to keep you safe.
Others can leave.
You can leave.
Why can't I leave?
Because your
holo-projectors
don't work in
the corridors.
My... what?
Please, sit down.
Doctor, you know I'm
your friend, right?
Yes. You're Kes.
Yes. Yes.
Do you remember me?
Of course
I remember you.
What an absurd question.
Oh, that's wonderful.
But why won't you
let me leave this place?
I'm trying to protect you.
Oh.
Well.
This isn't... such a bad place.
I remember...
there were a lot of people here,
wounded people.
I asked someone to...
state the nature
of the medical emergency,
and then inquired
as to the status
of their Chief
Medical Officer.
He was dead,
and then...
everyone disappeared.
I think that's when
you were activated
almost two years ago.
Oh, surely not.
It seems like... last week.
And there was a young woman.
I was rubbing her feet.
She was trying to decide
whether or not to have a child.
That was me.
How could that be?
I've never seen you before.
What else do you remember?
What a very odd question.
I remember many things.
Tell me.
I enjoy hearing them.
That doesn't seem
to be the case.
You find fault with
everything I say.
Doctor, don't think that.
You claim you're my friend,
but you don't even
call me by my name.
That's because
you don't have a name.
No name!
That's ridiculous! I...
My...
I demand you tell me
my name.
Wha-What's happening to me?
Captain,
the swarm is gaining on us.
They will be in weapons range
within five minutes.
Battle stations.
TUVOK:
The ships are now
within range, Captain,
but I do not detect
any indication
that they are
powering weapons.
Do you have any idea
what kind of weapon
systems they use?
Negative. Sensors show
no weapons signature at all.
They're only a hundred thousand
kilometers away now.
Arm all phaser banks.
Aye, Captain.
Captain.
Kes, what is it?
The Doctor is getting worse.
He's starting to dematerialize.
I'm afraid we're going
to lose him completely.
I know B'Elanna is busy,
but I wondered if Harry
could take a look at him.
I'm sorry, Kes, but
we're in the middle
of something here and I need
every hand at their posts.
KIM:
Captain, they're only
40,000 kilometers away.
Still no weapons signature.
Changing to evasive pattern
gamma-4.
Sick Bay.
Kes to Sick Bay.
How's the Doctor?
WOMAN:
No improvement.
He's still losing cohesion.
Computer, Deck 6.
Computer, initiate the Jupiter
Station Diagnostic Program.
COMPUTER:
Jupiter Station Program
is activated.
You again.
Now what?
The Doctor's program is
almost completely degraded.
We're going to lose him.
I'm not sure what you
expect me to do about it.
I expect you to help.
That's what you're programmed
to do, isn't it?
I have pointed out
over and over
I am a diagnostic tool,
not an engineer.
You have to try.
You're the only one
who can help now.
Young woman, you don't seem
to understand.
There are limitations
to my programming.
I can't just decide
to exceed them.
The Doctor did,
so why can't you?
You better start trying
because I'm not leaving here
until we accomplish
something.
It...
He... means a great deal
to you, doesn't he?
Yes, he does,
so start thinking
about his memory circuits
his holoprocessors,
his database, his matrix...
Why are you looking
at me like that?
You told me you had
the same matrix as the Doctor.
An adaptive,
heuristic matrix, yes.
In order to serve
as a diagnostic
for all the EMH programs.
Then couldn't your matrix
be substituted for his?
I...
I wouldn't have
thought of that.
But can it?
I'm not sure,
but even
if it were possible,
the same degradation would
eventually occur to my matrix.
What if yours were
grafted onto his?
Grafted?
In medicine, we
sometimes graft
portions of a healthy bone
onto a diseased one.
It gives the bone solidity
until it can heal.
Couldn't we do
something like that
with your matrices?
Well, it would require
synchronous transfer
of all the EMH databases
and subroutines.
Not an easy process,
mind you, but I...
I suppose
we could try.
Good. Let's get started.
I must point out that
you would no longer
have a diagnostic
program for the EMH.
If we don't do this, we won't
have an EMH to diagnose.
Hmm. Good point.
You'll have to return
to Sick Bay
and transfer
my program there.
Thank you,
Dr. Zimmerman.
Don't be premature.
I have no idea
if this is going to work.
Captain, our shield strength
just went to zero.
How could
that happen?
Each one of those little ships
is emitting
an interferometric pulse.
They're modulating in opposition
to our shield frequencies,
completely canceling them out.
All right, that's enough.
Tuvok, give them a phaser sweep
with the forward array.
Don't destroy any of them.
Just let them know we're not
going to sit here like ducks.
Aye, Captain.
What was that?
The interferometric pulses
they're emitting?
They've reflected
the energy of the phasers
right back to us.
Anything we fire is going to
affect us instead of them.
What about a photon torpedo?
Since our shield strength
is nonexistent,
I would not recommend it.
They're only 7,000 kilometers
away and still coming.
Harry, start analyzing
those interferometric pulses.
See if there's any pattern,
any code to them.
We might be able to
find a weakness.
I'm on it.
I'm increasingly dubious
as to the outcome
of this effort.
The EMH pathways are
seriously degraded.
They might not accept
a matrix overlay.
We have to try.
Please hurry.
I assure you I am working
as quickly as I can.
If I don't prepare
the multitronic paths properly,
there's no chance of success.
It's going to work, Doctor.
I'm sure of it.
What is?
( sighs )
Very well.
We're as ready
as we'll ever be.
I've programmed the computer
to install my heuristic matrix
onto the EMH primary circuitry.
We'll both have to
be taken off-line
for the overlay
to be made.
After the reinitialization
occurs,
you should activate
the Emergency Medical Hologram.
I understand.
You realize there will be
no second chance.
After this,
I will no longer exist.
Well, it's been
a brief existence,
but apparently a noble one.
Computer,
initiate program
Zimmerman Alpha-1.
COMPUTER:
Matrix overlay program
is active.
Please stand by.
Captain, they're
right on top of us.
I can't shake them.
Captain, they are
clamping onto our hull.
They're starting
to drain our systems.
KIM:
Captain, I've got a pattern
on the interferometric pulses.
It's a lattice connecting
all the ships to each other.
All right, here's what
we're going to do--
turn those pulses
right back on them.
Tuvok, lock phasers
on their nearest ship.
If we can destroy one of them,
there's every chance
the interferometric pulse
that links them together
will cause a chain reaction.
But the phaser fire will be
reflected back toward us.
Harry, modulate
our shield frequency
to an inverse harmonic
of the pulse.
That should allow the phasers
to hit the ship.
( yelling )
Ship's phasers are
locked on a target, Captain.
Tuvok, Harry, do it.
TUVOK:
The swarm of ships
has disbanded, Captain.
They are moving away.
KIM:
Shields are back
to full strength.
Good work, everyone.
Now let's get out of here.
It seems to be taking forever.
That's to be expected.
It's a complex procedure.
Dr. Zimmerman said
he didn't know if our doctor
would be restored to
his original programming
or if he'd regain the memories
of the past two years.
I think, at this point,
we'd be glad
to have him back no matter what.
COMPUTER:
Zimmerman program
Alpha-1 is now complete.
Computer, activate emergency
medical holographic program.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
It worked.
Doctor, I am
so glad to see you.
Are you ill, young woman?
No. N-No,
there's no emergency.
I, uh... I just wanted to see
if you were all right.
It is very irresponsible
to make such frivolous use
of the EMH.
Where's your
Chief Medical Officer?
We don't have one.
Actually, I have
an awful headache.
A headache?
Nurse, tricorder.
You're the nurse?
In a way.
Humph. This woman has
a mild inflammation
of the occipital tissues.
Hardly enough
to complain about,
but I'm willing to give you
a mild analgesic.
Thank you.
Get me the vasoconstrictor
and prepare a hypospray
with three percent
hydrocortilene.
Yes, Doctor.
( Doctor humming
"O soave fanciulla" )
( humming continues )
♪ In te, vivo ravviso ♪
♪ Il sogno ch'io vorrei ♪
♪ Sempre sognar... ♪