JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
stardate 50074.3.
We have detected evidence
that a wormhole
recently appeared
and then disappeared
in a nearby solar system.
We're on our way there
to investigate.
Based on the residual
neutrino levels,
I'd estimate it's been
at least six months
since the wormhole's
last appearance.
From the dispersal pattern
of the interstellar plasma,
it looks like
it isn't fixed.
It seems to be traveling
through space.
It may not be fixed
on this end,
but if it's shown up in the
same location more than once,
it's possible its exit point
is constant
and it's wagging
around the Delta Quadrant
like the tail on a dog.
PARIS:
Approaching
the last-known coordinates
of the wormhole, Captain.
All stop. Mr. Kim, initiate
continuous neutrino scans.
Aye, Captain.
Mr. Tuvok,
scan the planets
in this system
for life signs.
Maybe there's
someone around here
who can give us
some helpful information.
TUVOK:
I am picking up
an M-Class atmosphere
on the second planet.
Humanoid life signs.
However, metallurgic
analysis indicates
a preindustrial civilization.
A Bronze-Age level
of technology.
Curious, Captain.
What is?
I'm detecting evidence
that these people
have had contact
with the Alpha Quadrant.
What kind of evidence?
It is a modulated
energy discharge
that appears to be consistent
with the recent use...
of a replicator.
If they've got
a replicator,
it could mean
the wormhole leads
to the Alpha Quadrant
and that someone's
traveled through it.
I appreciate
your enthusiasm, Ensign,
but before we indulge
in too much speculation,
let's see if
we can back up
your assumptions
with some facts.
Commander Chakotay,
I want you and Lieutenant Paris
to go down to that planet
and have a look around.
Launch a high-resolution
reconnaissance probe
to gather information
about the local population's
dress and appearance.
Aye, Captain.
In the meantime, Ensign,
why don't you
and Lieutenant Torres
get started on a phase profile
of this elusive wormhole's
neutrino emissions.
Let's see if we can confirm that
it leads to the Alpha Quadrant.
Captain's Log,
stardate 50074.5.
Based on information provided
by the probe,
we have replicated local attire
for Commander Chakotay
and Lieutenant Paris.
They have gone to the surface
to investigate.
This is where we picked up
a replicator signature?
Hard to believe,
isn't it?
"Oh, those many years ago,
"the people's hearts
were sad and low,
"then the Sages
to the city came.
"They came upon a burning flame.
"Just as the seer
said they would,
"they lifted
Takar's blinding hood."
Well...
what did you think?
It was...
uh, very nice.
Nice?
I'll wager you've never heard
"The Song of the Sages"
more beautifully
or faithfully recited.
He's got a point.
We have never heard
"The Song of the Sages"
more beautifully recited.
As you know,
the first verse is free,
but the next verse will
cost you three frangs.
I'm sorry. Not today.
But I need money...
for ointment for my eye.
Please, gentlemen...
Oh, go away, old man.
Can't you see?
These are men of commerce.
They have no business
with your silly poems.
And may I say, gentlemen,
you both have very fine shoes.
Excuse me?
Well, the Sages say
you can tell a great deal
about a man from his shoes,
and I can tell from your shoes
that you're men of refinement...
affluence.
We've really
got to be going.
MALE:
Well, you're obviously
new in Takar.
Perhaps I could
interest you in some property.
No, thank you.
We're not planning
on settling here.
What about some transportation?
The Sages say "time's an asset."
And you shouldn't
waste your assets
walking everywhere you go.
You'd be wearing out
those fine shoes of yours.
( chuckles )
I'm sorry, but we're
really not interested.
Tom?
Excuse me.
I'm picking up a narrow-band
EM dampening field
around that building.
It looks like
some sort of temple.
Then I'd say the temple's
where we ought to look.
Oh, thank the Sages
I found you.
You can't enter the temple
without wearing your ears.
Look, friend, I
thought I told you...
What do you mean
"wearing your ears?"
( chuckles )
You're really not Takarian,
are you?
Nobody visits the temple
without displaying
at least one ear.
It must be some
sort of fetish.
If you're not wearing an ear,
you could be fined,
even arrested.
Wouldn't want that to happen.
And let me guess.
It just so happens
that you could sell us
a couple of these ears.
As a matter of fact...
I can.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I've been asked
to join Lieutenant Torres
and Ensign Kim
in the Science Lab
to hear what they've termed
as "very exciting news."
KIM:
We've been able to confirm
that the wormhole does lead
to the Alpha Quadrant.
The problem is
that on this end,
it's jumping from point
to point so quickly
that even at maximum warp,
by the time we got to
its next probable location,
it would be gone.
So we were thinking
if you can't bring
the ship to the wormhole,
bring the wormhole
to the ship.
We've detected a subspace
instability at our location
that's a result of the
wormhole's last appearance here.
If we could somehow amplify
and polarize that instability,
we might be able to get
the wormhole to reappear.
Sort of like using a magnet
to move a compass needle.
The question is:
how do we polarize
the instability?
Uh, we haven't figured
that part out yet.
Gentlemen, as the Sages say,
your goods are now my goods.
And my feet
are now cold.
Perhaps I could
interest you in some
discounted mining futures.
Don't push your luck.
You know, so far,
I can't say that I like
this town very much.
( loud clang )
On the other hand...
My friends...
the Holy Sages.
Behold...
the Holy Icon.
( crowd gasping )
Greed is eternal.
ALL:
MALE:
Now what other wisdom
have you learned from the Sages?
"A wise man can hear
profit in the wind."
ALL:
A wise man
can hear profit in the wind.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Janeway here.
We found the replicator,
Captain.
ALL:
A wise man can hear profit
in the wind.
MALE:
And now, dear friends,
in our great beneficence,
we will allow you
to come forward
to honor our greatness
and glorify our generosity.
Approach the Holy Sages.
Approach your gods
and speak your heart.
Ehh!
I am a sandal maker
from the poorest
quarter of the city.
The laziest, you mean.
Speak, my friend.
What is your business
with the Sages?
I am in need of assistance.
My sandal shop is failing.
I can no longer feed my family.
Same old song.
My wife,
and her mother,
my five children, the baby.
That's seven employees--
eight, if you count the infant.
How can your shop be failing?
You're not paying them, are you?
My mother-in-law is ill.
My children are very young.
Oh. Don't tell me
none of them are working.
Ignorant, lobeless fools!
Exploitation begins at home.
ALL:
I understand my mistake
and I promise
to begin exploiting my family
before the end of the day,
but could I have some food
and some medicine?
Ohh!
Until my business improves.
You shall have something
far more valuable--
one copy
of The Rules of Acquisition.
Cheapest binding possible.
That'll be ten frangs.
But I...
That's all for today.
You may return tomorrow.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The away team has returned
with some
very disturbing observations
about the situation
on the planet.
CHAKOTAY:
It seems the people
have a myth--
an epic poem called
"The Song of the Sages,"
which predicts the arrival
of two demigods
from the sky, the Sages,
who would rule over the people
as benevolent protectors.
But these Ferengi are
anything but benevolent.
What they've done is co-opt
the local mythology
by using advanced technology
like the replicator
to convince the people
that they're the two Sages
spoken of in the poem.
Of course,
being Ferengi,
they haven't just
co-opted the mythology.
They've cornered
the market... on everything.
It's disgusting, Captain.
The two Ferengi live
in a palatial temple,
while the people are lucky to
have a roof over their heads.
Apparently, it wasn't
always like that.
According to the
people that we met,
before the
Ferengi came,
the society may have
been primitive,
but it was flourishing.
What I'd like to know
is how two Ferengi got
to the Delta Quadrant.
We've been looking
into that. Mr. Tuvok.
According to Starfleet
computer records,
approximately seven years ago,
the Federation Starship
Enterprise hosted negotiations
for ownership
of the Barzan wormhole.
Included among the bidding
parties were two Ferengi--
minor functionaries
known as Arridor and Kol.
And this Barzan wormhole--
it's the same one
we've discovered now?
Apparently,
but we've confirmed
what nobody knew
at the time.
The wormhole is fixed
in the Alpha Quadrant,
but in the Delta Quadrant,
it jumps around.
It turned out
to be worthless.
But the Ferengi
were not aware of that,
and during a nefarious attempt
to secure
the wormhole for themselves,
they were pulled into it and
deposited in the Delta Quadrant.
Now that we've found them, what
are we going to do with them?
Well, I certainly don't intend
to leave them here
to continue exploiting
an innocent society.
How are you two
coming with getting
the wormhole back here
and reopened?
We've been bombarding the area
of the subspace instability
with verteron particles.
So far, everything is going
according to plan,
but it's tricky.
There are a hundred factors
that could deflect
it from this sector--
a gravimetric shift,
a solar flare...
And even if we're lucky
enough to get it here,
it won't be around
for long.
We'll have a very short
window of opportunity
to get through.
Well, if we can get
the wormhole here,
we'll be taking two additional
passengers with us.
We'll turn them over to Ferengi
authorities when we get there.
TUVOK:
Captain,
I must remind you
that the Ferengi are not
members of the Federation.
They are not bound
by the Prime Directive,
nor would it seem
that the Prime Directive
would allow us to interfere
with the internal affairs
of this society,
as much as we may disapprove
of what the Ferengi are doing.
The Federation did host
the negotiations,
and if it weren't
for those negotiations,
the Ferengi wouldn't be here.
So one could say...
without being unreasonable,
I think,
that the Federation is partially
responsible for what's happened
and therefore, duty bound
to correct the situation.
That is a most logical
interpretation, Captain.
FERENGI:
143...
144...
145...
146...
147, 148...
Profits from the Ga'nah Province
are down.
Hmm?
Are you listening to me?
I said profits from the Ga'nah
Province are down.
Down?!
Profits are down?
Hey, both of you
leave me alone.
Can't you see I'm trying
to conduct business here?
I'm... sorry...
Arridor.
It's just that...
they can't get enough
of my lobes.
Where were we?
Oh, yeah.
Profits are down?
And what are we going to do
about it?
What are you looking at me for?
Ask that idiot Kafar.
He's in charge of collections
in the Ga'nah Province.
Kafar!
You called, Great Sage?
What is the 95th Rule
of Acquisition?
Huh!
"Expand or die"?
He knows the rules
better than you do.
He does not.
And where is it
we've been trying
to expand... this month?
Into the Ga'nah
Province, Great Sage.
And who is in charge
of collections
in the Ga'nah Province?
I am, Great Sage.
Then why are profits down,
you idiot?!
Where's our money?!
Please forgive me,
Lesser Sage.
Oh, I told you to stop
calling me...
Who are you?
Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
starship Voyager.
The Federation?
♪Shut up, Kol.
Let me handle this.
What, may I ask
is the Federation doing
in the Delta Quadrant?
It's a long story,
but suffice it to say,
we've been stranded here
for the past two years.
We're on our way back
to the Alpha Quadrant
and we're taking
you with us.
This is an outrage.
We won't allow you
to tr...
You're crazy.
It would take decades
to get back from here.
Show them,
Mr. Tuvok.
We have been bombarding
a local subspace instability
with verteron particles.
If all goes
according to plan,
the Barzan wormhole
should reopen
at our present location
in a matter
of hours.
And if all doesn't go
according to plan?
One way or another,
you're coming with us.
We've been kidnapped.
Snatched...
from the embrace of bliss.
It's all over.
No more limitless profits...
no more unquestioning adulation
of the masses...
no more
quadruple lobe rubs.
If I'm not mistaken, Captain,
the Federation has rules,
and those rules forbid you
to interfere
with indigenous cultures.
What about
your interference?
You've taken
these people's religion
and manipulated it
for your own selfish purposes,
pretended to be their Sages.
Who's to say we aren't
their Sages, Captain?
Don't be ridiculous.
The song is sung of Sages
who can perform miracles,
which, thanks to
our replicator, we do.
The song is sung of men
coming from the sky
on a burning flame--
when we crash-landed
our shuttle
in their quaint
little town square,
trailing behind us
a roaring ribbon
of burning plasma.
You mean we really
are the Sages?
The point is, Captain,
that these people
have believed
for centuries
that gods,
known as the Sages,
would deliver them
from their strife.
To them...
we are those Sages.
What happens to a people
when they lose their gods?
Despair...
Mm-hmm.
Fear...
Mmm...
Confusion.
And how can you...
as a moral people,
blithely tear down
the spiritual structure
that has supported a community
since before their gods
were flesh?
What would you
be leaving them with?
Tell us, Arridor,
tell us.
Darkness...
Doubt...
Hopelessness.
That was beautiful.
Mr. Tuvok...
transport them back
to the surface.
We did it, Arridor.
We won.
We can't just leave
the Ferengi there
to continue exploiting
those poor people.
But Arridor is right.
We can't kidnap
their gods either.
What other option is there?
What if the gods
didn't just disappear
suddenly and inexplicably?
What if they left
voluntarily? Gracefully?
The gods would be gone, but
people would be prepared for it,
and they might accept it as
a natural, ordained occurrence.
Exactly.
But how do we get
two Ferengi
to just walk away
from a monopoly
on an entire economy?
What motivates a Ferengi?
Profit.
Then we must find
a way to make it
more profitable
for them to leave.
Or less profitable to stay.
How do we do that?
We have to out-Ferengi...
the Ferengi.
Mmm.
There we are.
I've reconfigured
the matter/antimatter generator
to produce an ionic
disruption field
around the temple square.
No more
unexpected beam-outs.
Let's see how smart
those humans
think they are now.
( loud knock at door )
Kafar!
You called, Great Sage?
Find out who
has the audacity
to disturb us in
our Divine Vault.
Uh...
And make it quick.
Who has the audacity
to disturb the Holy Sages
in their Divine Vault?
Grand Nagus!
Not the Grand Nagus.
I'm his official messenger--
the Grand Proxy.
But, Grand Proxy,
how did you...?
Through the Barzan wormhole.
The humans stabilized it
temporarily,
and were kind enough
to send a probe through
informing us of your...
impressive operation.
Well, of course
the Grand Nagus,
or his official messenger
the Grand Proxy,
is always
welcome in our
little world--
our rather poverty-stricken
and we're thrilled he
has taken an interest
in our very modest operation.
If I were you,
I'd save the groveling
for the Nagus himself.
Y-You mean, the Grand Nagus
is coming here, too?
Of course not, you idiot.
You two are
going to him.
You've been recalled.
Recalled?
We're ruined.
GRAND PROXY:
You will be leaving immediately.
This is not a time
to lose one's lobes.
I'll think of something.
Perhaps the Grand Nagus
doesn't understand
that profits in this market
depend upon our presence.
You see, to these people,
we're, well... gods, actually.
Without us to make the fools
cower in submission,
there will be
no profits to be had.
The Grand Nagus knows
all about your little scheme--
"The Song of the Sages"
and all the rest of it.
Very clever.
But he wants you
and all your acquisitions
back on Ferenginar
before the wormhole
closes again.
I'm sure the Grand Nagus
wouldn't want to lose
such a lucrative
revenue stream.
The wormhole seems to open
and close on its own
every seven or eight years.
We would be willing
to forward a fair share
of the profits
every time it does.
Say, hmm... 20 percent?
That's coming out
of your half.
Shut up.
The Grand Nagus
has no intention
of losing profits
from this market.
That's why he's already
got a team of scientists
investigating
the human's technology--
to see if we can find a way
to open and close the wormhole
whenever we want.
Then perhaps
the Grand Nagus
could simply
recall one of us
and leave the other behind
to administer
the operation.
You could take Kol
back with you.
Hey, wait a minute!
I don't think that...
That's enough!
The Grand Nagus
has recalled you both.
It's nonnegotiable.
Of course, the Nagus
doesn't want to upset
the local population.
He may want to send others
in your place.
That's why he wants you
to make a little speech
telling the people that their
Holy Sages have been recalled
to the Divine Treasury,
or whatever it is the people
around here call it.
Then he wants you
to tell them not to worry--
that everything
will be all right without you.
Then he wants you to thank them
for their generosity.
Thank them?
The 299th Rule of Acquisition--
"Whenever you exploit someone,
it never hurts to thank them.
That way, it's easier
to exploit them the next time."
Wait a minute.
There's only 285
Rules of Acquisition.
You've been gone
a very long time.
Oh...
By the way, did I mention
that the Nagus is appropriating
all your holdings?
What?
All?
All.
The least you can
do is let us keep
the females.
I'll be back in 20 minutes
to approve your speech.
I suggest you start writing.
You!
Come with me!
Of course,
Greater Sage.
What are we going to do?
What a Ferengi always does
in a situation this grave.
Panic?
No, you idiot!
He goes to the Rules
of Acquisition.
Oh.
Unabridged
and fully annotated
with all 47 commentaries,
all 900 major
and minor judgments,
all 10,000
considered opinions.
There is a Rule
for every conceivable situation.
Looks like Neelix is pulling off
quite a performance.
There you are.
Don't push.
There's plenty to go around.
Oh, you're quite welcome.
Is he another Sage?
Have you ever seen
a Sage give away money?
"Grand proxy, avoidance of..."
Mm-mm.
"Grand proxy, censure by..."
"Grand proxy,
encounters with..."
"See 'hopeless situation.'"
I told you there was no rule.
Then it's time
to invoke the unwritten rule.
The unwritten rule?
When no appropriate
rule applies...
make one up.
( chuckles )
That's a very good rule.
Now, let's see...
What should it be?
The Grand Proxy is the Nagus's
official messenger, right?
I've got it.
When the messenger comes
to appropriate your profits...
kill the messenger.
( chuckling )
( laughing gleefully )
Thank you!
Arridor!
Kol!
Show yourselves!
We can't keep
the Grand Nagus waiting!
If you say so.
What is the meaning of this?
You're not very bright
for a Grand Proxy.
Ex-Grand Proxy.
But the Grand Nagus...
Is on the other side
of the galaxy.
( yells )
( grunting )
Wait!
I'm not...
I'm not the Grand Proxy.
Oh, no?
Who are you then?
Stop! My name is Neelix.
Neelix? That's not
a Ferengi name.
Wait!
I'm not Ferengi.
What?
I've never even met
the Grand Nagus.
A likely story.
It's true.
I'm wearing a disguise.
I'm really a Talaxian,
a crewman on Voyager.
If you're not Ferengi,
prove it!
I'm not sure how.
Doesn't that hurt?
I can't feel a thing.
He really isn't a Ferengi.
On your feet.
All right,
Talaxian,
back to your ship.
And tell those humans
to keep their hands
out of our pockets...
or else.
And stay out!
We won.
We won!
No, my friend.
Not exactly.
To be precise...
we won again.
( laughs )
What happened?
Suffice it to say,
they know I'm not
the Grand Proxy.
Oh, great.
Let's get to the shuttle.
Who are you?
I'm... uh...
well...
You are another Holy One,
aren't you?
That's right.
Uh... another Holy One.
Then you'll appreciate this.
"The Sages in the sky did dwell
"upon white clouds
that held them well,
"until the sentry rang the bell,
the Holy Sages never fell."
That'll be three frangs, please.
But we didn't ask
you to recite it.
You heard it, didn't you?
CHAKOTAY:
Your poem's very nice,
but we're in a hurry.
No, please, sir.
My eye.
Look, friend, I'm sorry
about your eye, really, but...
Wait a minute.
Wasn't your patch...
on the other side?
Oh.
Sir?
We've got to go.
Wait, please.
I'll throw in
another verse gratis.
"But when the ringing
called them here,
from the sky
they did appear..."
Tell me something.
What happens to the Sages
at the end of the song?
Oh... let me see now.
The final verse.
It's been a very long time,
you know.
Um...
Those are very handsome shoes
you have, sir.
Ah, yes.
It's coming
back to me now.
"And there amid
the eastern lights,
"three new stars
appeared that night
"and with the ringing
of the bell,
"the Sages knew
where they must dwell.
"The Holy Pilgrim led them back,
"high into the sky of black
"and riding
on the wings of fire,
the holy men
rose higher and higher..."
Wait a minute.
I know who you are.
I am the Holy Pilgrim.
( insects chirping )
( clears throat )
Did you hear that?
The Holy Pilgrim.
The Holy Pilgrim?
PARIS: The Holy Pilgrim!
CHAKOTAY:
The Holy Pilgrim!
( crowd exclaiming outside )
I have come
to fulfill the destiny
that is prophesied
in "The Song of the Sages."
What in the name
of eternal destitution
is going on here?
Ah, there you are.
Do you not recognize me?
I am the Holy Pilgrim.
The Holy Pilgrim?
Who's the Holy Pilgrim?
Quiet, you idiot.
This man is no Holy Pilgrim.
He's a Talaxian!
ALL:
Talaxian?
Oh, no, Great Sage.
You are mistaken.
I am indeed
the Holy Pilgrim
and just as "The Song
of the Sages" promises,
"I have come
to lead you back,
high into the sky
of black."
( startled murmuring )
I have prayed
for this day to come.
Lead them back.
CROWD ( chanting ):
Lead them back. Lead them back.
Lead them back.
What do they mean,
lead us back?
I don't know. It must be
part of the song.
I told you we should've
listened to the whole thing.
Well, it looks
as though you two
will be heading off to see
the Grand Nagus after all.
We'll see about that.
This man...
This man?
Is a false pilgrim.
( crowd exclaiming )
He's come to steal
your profits.
( shocked exclamations )
I'm not a false pilgrim
and I'll prove it.
That's our cue.
Chakotay to Voyager.
On my mark.
Stand by to initiate
the photon burst, Mr. Kim.
Aye, Captain.
Captain, I am still unable
to penetrate
the Ferengi dampening field.
If the away team
experiences difficulties,
we will be unable
to beam them out.
Keep working on it.
In the meantime,
we'll just have to rely
on their ingenuity
to get themselves out of there
if trouble arises.
The song says that
"Amid the eastern lights,
three new stars
appeared that night."
( all agreeing )
Look, my friends.
Look.
Right up there.
Now.
Initiating photon bursts.
( all gasping )
( gasping )
It's a trick.
He's a fraud, I tell you.
Kafar, arrest this man.
Well, arrest him!
( yelling )
Ow! Stop!
My ears!
What do you think
you're doing?!
Like the song says,
Lesser Sage...
"With the ringing of the bell,
the Sages knew
where they must dwell."
( yelling )
Ow!
Like the song says,
you Sages, it's time for you
to go back where
you came from.
MALE:
Yes! Yes!
To the sky!
And they must go
on wings of fire!
ALL:
Wings of fire! Wings of fire!
Wings of fire!
( crowd yelling )
We are your gods!
This is outrageous!
Look, we are your gods.
I am your god.
We're the Sages.
Hands off of your god.
No. No.
Wait a minute, people.
There's no reason to interpret
"The Song of the Sages"
so literally.
Kafar!
Kafar! Stop them!
We are fulfilling
the destiny of the Sages.
I am the Holy Pilgrim
and I have come to tell you
that there's another verse
to the song.
It's uh, uh...
Please, don't burn
the Holy Ones.
I am sorry,
Holy Pilgrim,
but that's not
part of the song.
CROWD ( chanting ):
Wings of fire! Wings of fire!
Wings of fire!
Commander, I think now
would be a very good time
for that beam-out.
CROWD:
Wings of fire! Wings of fire!
Wings of fire!
We've got to disable
the dampening field,
so they can beam us
out of here.
Where's the generator?
BOTH:
In the vault!
CROWD:
Wings of fire!
Wings of fire! Wings of fire!
( chanting continues )
We still cannot establish
a transporter lock, Captain.
Boosting power to
the annular confinement beam.
Arridor?
What is it now?
We had seven years
of pure profit.
We did, didn't we?
I can't shut it down.
Stand back.
The Holy Ones have ascended!
( crowd cheering )
JANEWAY:
Is everyone okay down there,
Commander?
We're all here
in one piece, Captain.
Good work.
Report to the Bridge as soon
as everything is in order.
We'll be entering the wormhole
in approximately seven minutes.
Acknowledged.
We're not going
through any wormhole
without our possessions.
Listen, friend, you're
lucky to be alive.
We beamed your shuttle
to the shuttle bay.
As for the rest
of your possessions,
they're back in the
hands of the people
you stole them from.
Ensign Murphy,
escort these men
to secured quarters.
This is outrageous.
I'll hold you
personally responsible
for any losses we suffer.
We'll sue!
Shield status, Mr. Tuvok.
Shields are optimal.
Mr. Paris,
engage maneuvering thrusters
and ease us into position.
Aye, Captain.
DOCTOR:
Sick Bay to Lieutenant Tuvok.
Go ahead, doctor.
Ensign Murphy was just found
unconscious on Deck 2.
It's a severe concussion.
We suspect foul play.
Murphy was escorting
the Ferengi
to their quarters.
TUVOK:
Captain, security
has been breached
in the shuttle bay.
Seal that airlock,
Mr. Tuvok.
The Ferengi have phasered
the shuttle bay door.
They are exiting the ship.
Activating emergency
containment field.
They're setting a course
for the planet, Captain.
Lock a tractor beam
on to that shuttle.
The gravitational effects
of the wormhole
are refracting the beam.
I can't get a lock.
The Ferengi are hailing us,
Captain.
On screen.
Thank you for all your
assistance, humans.
It was lovely
doing business with you.
We'll be heading
back into orbit
to transport our
acquisitions aboard.
( both laughing )
JANEWAY:
Beam those men back
now, Mr. Kim.
I'm trying, but the targeting
scanners are out of phase.
Try setting the scanners
to a narrow-band
subspace frequency.
( alarm beeps )
What is it?
They're trying to beam us
back to their ship again.
They're using some sort
of subspace carrier wave.
Do something!
Shields to maximum.
Shields are at maximum!
Send out a high-energy
graviton pulse.
Let's see their transporter
signal cut through that.
Captain, the Ferengi
are emitting
a graviton pulse.
It's throwing the targeting
scanners off again.
Not only that, it's
destabilizing the wormhole.
Captain, a gravitational eddy
from the wormhole
is attracting
the Ferengi shuttle.
They're being pulled in.
Reverse thrusters!
They're off-line!
( both screaming )
Follow them in before that
wormhole collapses, Mr. Paris.
PARIS:
Aye, Captain.
Resetting
the coordinates.
Captain, the entrance
to the wormhole is moving.
The Ferengi graviton pulse
must have increased
its rotational momentum.
Adjusting course to follow.
( console buzzing )
( sighs )
It's too fast for us, Captain.
I need more speed.
Mr. Tuvok, divert auxiliary
power to the thrusters.
It's not enough.
Initiate a high intensity
impulse burst.
Mr. Kim, reinitiate
the verteron field.
Maybe we can attract
the wormhole back.
The Ferengi graviton pulse
knocked the wormhole
completely off
its subspace axis.
It's jumping erratically
now on both ends.
Options?
There are none.
Mr. Paris, reset a course
for the Alpha Quadrant.
Warp 6.
Aye, Captain.
Look.
KAFAR:
The Holy Ones are going home!