Janeway: Captain's Log,
Stardate 50203.1.
We're three days away
from Enara Prime--
home of the passengers
we picked up from a colony
in the Fima system.
Our high warp capability
has greatly reduced the time
it normally takes them
to make the journey home.
In return,
the Enarans have shared
their energy conservation
technology with us,
and perhaps more importantly,
their friendship.
You've never
been there?
Well, the trip back to the
homeland usually takes so long.
I didn't want
to see it that badly.
I've spent my whole life
in the Fima colony
and I've always
considered it my home.
You'll change your mind
when you see the Daeleus
cliffs at dawn.
Yes, I've heard
they're beautiful.
You'll know what
"beautiful" truly means,
when you stand on the
cliffs on a rainy morning
and watch the raindrops...
turn to mist when they
hit the molten sea.
TORRES: That sounds wonderful.
( console beeping )
It looks like our new components
are still slightly out of sync
with your EPS system.
I can't isolate it.
We'll have to check
through all of them.
Maybe Harry could
give us a hand.
Well, I'm sure he would
if you asked him.
Harry, you
got a minute?
Sure.
Could you help us check
the modified power relays?
There is
a minor flow problem.
I'd be happy to help.
Good. Then we'll get started
first thing in the morning.
Well, if we're done
for the night,
maybe we could all go
get something to eat.
Thank you, but I'll be
headed back to bed.
I'm sure you young people
will manage without me.
Good night.
So, I guess it'll just
be the three of us.
Actually, getting some rest
sounded like a pretty good idea.
Why don't you...
go on without me?
No, really, I insist.
( sighs )
( tapping )
What took you so long?
( laughing )
Aah!
( both laughing )
Korenna...
Shh!
( both panting )
CHAKOTAY:
B'Elanna.
B'Elanna, wake up.
What?
Your duty shift
started 20 minutes ago.
I tried to reach you on the com,
but you didn't answer.
I guess...
I guess I must have
slept right through it.
Sorry.
Are you feeling all right?
Yes, of course.
I'll be there in a minute.
This is the second morning
you've been late.
I'll make up the time.
It won't happen again.
I'm not concerned
about the duty schedule,
B'Elanna.
If there's something wrong...
I'm fine.
You mean, fine like when
you insisted on finishing
the hoverball championship
with a broken ankle?
I mean there's
nothing wrong.
I was only late
because...
I've been having
these dreams.
They're very intense.
That's all.
( sighs )
Intensely bad?
No.
Just the opposite.
So they're enjoyable?
Stimulating?
They are the most
sensual dreams
I've ever had
in my life...
and they feel
absolutely real.
I don't suppose
you've been dreaming
about anyone in particular?
Nobody you know.
Actually...
he's nobody
I know either.
He's Enaran.
One of our passengers?
No. No.
In the dreams, I know him.
More than that,
I'm in love with him.
But it's not really me
in the dream.
It's somebody else entirely.
In a way, it's...
liberating.
I'm sure.
So I assume I won't
have to write up
a report on your
chronic oversleeping?
If you say a word
about this to anyone...
I know. You'll rip
my heart out
and eat it raw.
Your secret's
safe with me.
So, what exactly
is this big surprise?
All I know is that Neelix
has been working
on it all afternoon.
He wouldn't even let me
in there to get a snack.
( delicate, ethereal
music playing )
NEELIX:
Welcome to Enara!
It's... very...
colorful.
Specifically, the colors
of the Enaran flag.
The decor, the
music, the menu--
All authentically
Enaran.
What happened to
the tables and chairs?
Enarans don't use them.
After a big meal,
you can just lie back
and take a nap.
Very practical.
It's a little cold
in here, isn't it?
Perhaps a bit chillier
than we're used to,
but just about
perfect for...
Enarans. I got it.
You must try
some of these
delightful algae puffs.
They're fresh
from the oven.
ENARAN FEMALE:
Harry?
Maybe later.
( music continues )
( music ends )
Oh, that was wonderful.
What a lovely
piece of music.
You should thank
Jora Mirell.
She composed it.
I still think you're
rushing the harmonics
in the second movement.
I love music. I've always
regretted
that I never learned
to play an instrument.
I'd be glad
to help you if you like.
I'd like it
very much.
I'm sure I could
find time
for a few lessons.
( playing instrument expertly)
( gasps )
Captain?
I'm all right.
I did understand
you correctly
that you wanted to share
my knowledge of music?
I didn't realize
you were offering
to share it so directly.
The sensation was just
a little... overwhelming.
I am terribly sorry,
Captain.
I assumed since you knew of
our telepathic abilities...
I-I never would have dreamed
of making a connection
without your consent.
You intended
to give me a gift...
and it was wonderful.
Your abilities allow you
to transfer knowledge
from your own mind
to another's?
Not precisely.
We're able to share
our experiences
through a telepathic link.
I remembered lessons
and hours of practice.
Were those
your experiences?
Intriguing.
Remarkable.
You take a couple
of these...
roll them around
like this...
and voilà!
Your hands are clean
and disinfected.
The Enarans
are very hygienic.
Hmm.
I haven't seen
Lieutenant Torres
around here tonight.
I suppose
she's putting in
another late night
in Engineering.
Actually, I think
she might have gone
to bed early tonight.
I'm not one to dictate
who your friends are,
but I'm sure you can see
as clearly as I can
that some friends
are less suitable than others.
Like Dathan?
Yes. You promised
you wouldn't
see him anymore
and then I heard
you were talking
to him again
the other day.
He came up to me
on the street.
I couldn't help it.
Korenna,
don't you see
I am thinking of him
as well as you?
Now, you only
encourage him this way
and that isn't
very fair, is it?
What isn't fair is
that you treat him
like everybody else.
He's different.
If you just talked to him,
you'd understand that.
You know, one of the things
I love about you most
is your compassion
for others.
But you're still young.
You don't realize that
there are some people
that might take advantage
of that compassion.
Now, I want you
to promise me,
if he comes up to you again,
you'll just walk away.
That should be
clear enough.
I'm sure.
And finish your tarin juice.
It's good for you.
He's gone.
( giggling )
I should go.
He's leaving for work soon.
It's safer to wait.
You know, this will
only encourage me.
I hope so.
( laughing )
( startled cry )
No! No!
( gasping )
We've completed
the modifications
on the primary EPS
conduits.
I have a crew starting
on the backup systems.
Can you get it done
before we drop off
the Enarans?
Yes. We'll have to pull
some longer shifts,
but two more days
should do it.
Is there something
else on your mind?
Those dreams
I've been having...
um, they're getting
kind of strange.
In what way?
Last night,
in the middle of the dream,
I was...
kissing him--
My lover--
And suddenly he was dead.
Burned.
B'Elanna...
But there's more going on
than just a love affair.
I'm having a relationship
with this man,
but my father doesn't approve,
so we have to sneak around.
It's like each new dream
advances the story.
It sounds like
a holonovel.
But it feels like
it's actually happening.
I mean, physically,
emotionally,
it's no different
from real life.
I've never had dreams
like this before.
It can't be a coincidence
that this is going on
while we have a group
of telepaths on board.
Exactly.
I want to find out more
about what these
Enarans can do.
Why don't you ask
your friend in Engineering?
I'm going to.
I'll talk to the Captain.
She should know about anything
that might involve our guests.
Right.
JARETH:
Once, I stood where you are
during the early days
of interstellar exploration.
It was an important
leap forward for our people,
and I was proud
to be part of it.
Today, with the advent
of terraforming,
we stand ready
to take another leap forward
into an era
of expansion
and colonization.
You will show us
the way.
There are some
who resist progress.
Do not let the voices
of fear and ignorance
discourage you.
Claim your
rightful place
as leaders of a new era.
The future of Enara
is in your hands.
Now, today, we honor
a group of young people
who represent our best hope
for that future.
It is a great
pleasure to give
this first award
to my own daughter, Korenna.
I'm so very proud of you.
DATHAN:
It looks good on you.
What are you doing here?
Today's important for you.
I wanted to be here.
I'm glad you came.
( sighs )
I know this award
will help me get
into the District
Education Center.
I could be a junior instructor
in less than a year.
I'm really happy
for you.
Maybe you could take
the entrance examination, too.
You know
that's impossible.
I can't go
to the Center.
Nothing is impossible
if you want it badly enough.
I want us to be together.
I love you, Korenna.
It's just
so frustrating.
I can't stand being away
from you all the time.
Oh, I know.
Oh, I wish I could hold you
right now.
What would you do
if you could?
I'll show you.
( breathing heavily )
( bell tolls )
( voices approaching )
I'll see you tonight.
No. No. There's going
to be a big dinner
with my father's friends.
( bell tolls )
Tomorrow night,
then.
Tomorrow.
( tolling continues )
MALE:
Single file. Identification.
MALE 2:
Next.
Let's go.
Have identification ready.
This way, this way.
All the way out.
Let's move.
B'Elanna!
Can you hear me?
Kes to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency.
( gasps )
Good to see you're
awake, Lieutenant.
What happened?
I found you unconscious
in the corridor
near Engineering.
I was dreaming again.
Not according to your
cortical theta wave readings.
The pattern clearly indicated
that you were
experiencing memories.
Specifically,
implanted memories.
Implanted?
By the Enarans?
There's strong evidence
of telepathic activity
in your
frontal lobe.
My experience with
the Enarans' telepathy
seems to be very different
from yours.
Jor Brel was standing near me
when I received his memories.
Were there any Enarans near
you when you had your dreams?
No, I was alone every time.
You've also
been asleep
or unconscious every time.
The shared memories
feel like...
vivid dreams to you.
In the Lieutenant's
case, the memories
seem to have been placed
in her unconscious.
They're only emerging
when her conscious mind
is inactive.
Why did she pass out?
The synaptic patterns
of the implanted memories
are not quite compatible
with her neural pathways.
There's been some minor cortical
damage, which I've corrected.
Can you prevent
further damage?
This inhibitor will control
her theta-wave activity.
That should suppress
the memories.
I won't have any more
of the dreams?
That's the idea.
What's wrong?
If the dreams stop,
I'll never know what happens
to these people.
I mean, this woman,
Korenna,
I... I feel
what she feels.
And right now,
she is torn and confused
about her loyalties,
and I don't know what I'm--
what she's going to do.
DOCTOR:
I don't think satisfying
your curiosity
is worth risking brain damage,
Lieutenant.
I'm giving you
the next two days off duty.
Use them to rest.
I'll speak with Brel
and find out what's
happening to you.
I'd like to come with you,
Captain.
I'd rest a lot better
if I had some answers.
I find it impossible
that any of us could be
doing this purposely.
You do possess
the capability
to share your experiences
without mutual consent.
Yes, but, uh,
it just isn't done.
I-I know that we had
a misunderstanding
before, Captain,
but I assure you,
we have strict ethics.
We're not suggesting
otherwise.
We're only trying
to find out
how this is happening.
Well, I have heard of instances
where members of some alien
races have been affected
by the slight telepathic field
we generate, but nothing
as intense as what
your Lieutenant
has described.
Well, according to our Doctor,
they're memories.
That's possible.
She may be picking up
stray thoughts and memories
from every Enaran on the ship.
It must be terribly confusing.
Perhaps that's why her
mind has organized it
into a kind
of narrative.
Are you saying that
I'm making this all up?
No, no, no.
Some elements
may very well have come
from our actual experiences.
I confess I...
I may have crawled
into a bedroom window or two
in my youth.
You mentioned
a citizenship award.
There are several
past recipients in our group.
We may be each contributing
some small details
to your story.
Nothing really happened
the way I remember it?
It's highly unlikely.
We appreciate your help,
Jor Brel.
I wish there was something more
that I could do.
I truly regret any ill effects
that our presence here
has caused you.
Well, fortunately, those
effects are under control now.
The Doctor was able
to suppress the memories.
I'm very glad to hear that.
( door opens, closes )
His explanation is plausible.
B'Elanna?
I don't know.
Those dreams are so real...
Maybe he's right.
The Enarans haven't
shown any hint of subterfuge--
Any hidden agenda.
They've been nothing
but straightforward and honest.
You're in no
immediate danger.
They'll be gone in another day.
The situation
will resolve itself.
And yet, you fully intend
to continue investigating.
I wonder how long it's been
since I did anything
that surprised you.
I share your concern, Captain.
We haven't ruled out
the possibility
that this may be
a deliberate act.
I want to talk to more
of the Enarans,
see what they have to say.
I'll talk to Jessen and Mirell.
They've been working with me
in Engineering.
You've done enough already,
B'Elanna.
I want you to get some rest.
But...
You need to get away from this.
We'll take it from here.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50211.4.
We're approaching Enara
and preparing to host a
farewell party for our guests.
They've made every effort
to help us understand
their telepathic abilities,
but it's still a mystery
why they've affected
Lieutenant Torres so strongly.
( sighs )
( instrument powers off )
Korenna, are you ready?
You'll do well.
I'll be there
with you.
This is all voluntary,
isn't it?
They want to be resettled?
Of course.
Although it's impossible
to understand
what these Regressives want.
They simply don't
think like we do.
How do we relate to people
who refuse all but the most
primitive technology?
Who live their lives
without a communications
interlink
or microfusion generators?
If that's the way
they want to live...
why can't they?
Well, they can.
That's why we're
helping them to resettle,
so that they can be
completely comfortable
practicing a way of life
that they've chosen.
They could do that here
in their village.
You wouldn't say that if you'd
ever been inside that place.
Do you realize they won't
even use radioseptics
to sterilize their homes,
or their hands before they eat?
It's a miracle they haven't
started a plague by now.
Then... it's dangerous
to have them living here.
Yes, it is.
And we've been tolerant
for a very long time,
but I think by now
even they realize
that they'd be better off
living somewhere else.
But some of them
want to stay here.
Well, there are always some
people who resist change
even if they know
it's best for them,
but once they see
their friends and family
happily settled
in the new colony,
they'll want to go as well.
Demalos.
MALE:
Demalos, move along.
Sanric.
MALE:
Farran.
What's going
to happen to us?
You'll have a new place
to live with your own kind.
You'll be much happier there.
Please...
Move it along.
...can you
tell me...
I only want to know
where we're going.
Peshar.
Alaris.
Dathan Alaris!
Where is he?
He couldn't be leaving today.
Did you warn him?
Did you tell him
he was on the list?
I didn't even know
that he was.
You put his name there,
didn't you,
to keep him away from me.
FEMALE:
Fredik! Don't!
No!
( gasps )
Computer, locate Jora Mirell.
Jora Mirell is in her quarters.
( moaning )
I'll get you to Sick Bay.
No.
I have to give you
the rest of it.
You are Korenna.
These are your memories.
Yes.
Why give them to me?
You won't deny the truth.
We've been hiding it.
I couldn't anymore.
They found out
I was sharing it with you.
Who did?
Don't let the memories die.
Promise me.
I don't understand...
( playing soft music )
( tapping )
( music stops )
( tapping louder )
My father's home.
If he hears you...
What happened?
One of your friends
made some trouble
on the resettlement line today.
You were on the list too.
Where were you?
Some of us got away.
We're leaving tonight.
Come with me.
Korenna, it's the only way
we can be together now.
You're asking me
to abandon my family,
my career...
Yes, I am.
Leave it all behind.
What's happening here
is wrong, Korenna.
Don't be a part
of it anymore.
It's just a resettlement.
It is more than that.
My uncle and his family
were resettled two months ago
and we haven't heard
from them since.
Nobody I know
has had any contact
with this new colony
we're supposed to be going to.
There could be
a perfectly good reason...
There are stories.
I've heard that the transports
don't really go anywhere,
that the passengers
just get vaporized
in some kind
of thermal sweep.
Korenna, thousands of us
have gone already.
We are being slaughtered.
It's ridiculous.
No one is being killed.
My father told me--
Your father is lying to you!
I'm sorry, but you have
got to make a choice.
You can't go on trying to
believe in both of us anymore.
Either he is right and you
should never see me again,
or I'm right, and he is
part of a terrible crime.
No. My father
is a good man.
I can show you
how we're rounded up
for these voluntary
resettlements,
how the soldiers
treat Regressives
who won't go quietly.
I know it is hard to face,
but you have to.
It is too important.
Now let me show you.
No, I...
( knock at door )
JARETH: Korenna?
Come in.
I was, I was just practicing.
I've always said
you have the talent
to play professionally.
How are you feeling?
I've been better.
Don't think
about it anymore.
That Regressive was
completely irrational.
He attacked you
for no reason.
KORENNA:
Maybe he thought
he had a reason.
Maybe he was afraid.
I know there are some
very disturbing rumors
coming from these people.
You may have heard them
from that boy.
You know, the thing
that is so insidious
about these Regressives
is that they pretend
to be passive,
not harming anyone
and all the while
they are spreading their lies,
trying to make you believe
these awful things.
Why would they do that?
They have some twisted ideas
about resisting progress,
which they think
gives them the right
to hold us back
in any way that they can.
They're trying
to undermine us,
to cause
dissent and doubt.
Just look at how
they've affected you.
But...
what they're saying
is so horrible.
Yes, but it isn't very
plausible.
Korenna, think.
A secret conspiracy
against their people?
Organized murder
on such an enormous scale?
Do you really believe
that your family and friends
are capable of that?
No.
'Course not.
Now, I know how hard it is
for you to accept
that anyone, even Regressives,
could lie
about something like that,
but it is all part
of their manipulation.
These people have
no conscience.
They'll say anything
to get what they want.
Like that boy Dathan.
Has he told you
he's in love with you?
He's not.
It's his way
of gaining your sympathy.
And not only yours.
I've seen him talking
to quite a number
of young women.
Has he been asking you
to trust him?
He's poisoning you
against your own people.
Even your own family.
Hmm?
That's very cruel.
No wonder
you've been confused.
But now you understand
what these people
are really like.
You!
DATHAN:
No. No!
( scuffling )
( door closes )
( angrily raised voices )
( locks clicking )
JARETH:
These criminals represent
a growing threat
to Enaran society.
As responsible citizens,
we must fight back!
( shouting agreement )
With their punishment,
we send a clear signal
to all Regressives.
We will protect
ourselves and our ideals
from their
destructive influence
by whatever means necessary.
( crowd cheering )
( crowd shouting )
CROWD ( chanting ):
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes!
GIRL:
Why did they
all move away?
KORENNA:
Because they didn't want to live
with the rest of us anymore.
Why?
The Regressive people
had very strange ideas
about how to live.
They didn't want to
learn new things
or use any of the technology
that we tried to share
with them.
They decided to live
somewhere else on their own,
and we let them go.
But they couldn't take
very good care of themselves.
They fought
with each other.
They spread all
kinds of diseases.
And they all died?
They destroyed themselves.
It was very sad.
But... we can learn
from their mistakes.
That's why we keep
this gate here--
To remind us never to be
stubborn and backward
like they were.
We'll remember.
I know you will.
I'd like to indulge in a new
custom that I've learned.
It's called making a toast.
( people chuckling )
To Captain Janeway
and her gracious crew.
We are very grateful to you
for bringing us home.
You will always
have friends here.
Murderers.
Lieutenant.
You tried to hide
what you did, but I know.
I saw everything.
The Regressives,
the executions.
Wiping out
an entire population,
and then
blaming them for it.
This is most uncomfortable,
Captain.
Perhaps a more private
discussion would be...
No, that's what you've been
doing all along--
Hiding the truth.
Hoping that it would
just die away quietly!
Please.
This has to come out.
I think it's time
we all understood
what's been happening here.
My dreams--
They are real memories
from Jora Mirell.
When she-- When all
of them were younger,
there was a group of people
they called Regressives.
They just wanted to lead
a different kind of life,
but... but they don't exist
anymore, do they?
You exterminated them.
These accusations
are completely untrue.
You spent your whole life
covering it up,
and then you realized
that someone was passing
the memories on to me.
So you...
you used me to figure out
who it was,
and then you killed her,
but, you know,
you were too late,
because Korenna gave me the last
of her memories before she died.
Korenna Mirell
is dead?
And you have evidence
that she was murdered?
No, they made it look like
it was natural causes.
You should know, Lieutenant,
that I spoke with
Jora Mirell yesterday.
I asked her specifically about
the memories you experienced.
She claimed not to know
anything about them.
Of course she would say that.
She was afraid for her life.
No, you're lying. The Enarans
would never do anything
like what you're saying.
It's unthinkable.
It is the truth.
I know that you don't
want to believe it.
In fact, they're counting on
that. They always have.
I know B'Elanna,
and I trust her.
It can't hurt to listen.
Nobody thinks you're lying,
Lieutenant.
The poor woman has been ill
for a long time.
Her memories may be distorted
or perhaps your perception
of them was colored
by elements
from your culture.
No.
I know that it's easier for you
to believe
that I'm crazy
or hallucinating,
but this woman
shared her life--
Her whole identity-- With me.
I was with her every
step of the way
as she convinced herself
that what she did--
Betraying the man she loved,
playing her part
in the massacre--
That it was
all somehow
for the good
of Enaran society.
She showed me everything.
No apologies, no request
for forgiveness,
just the truth.
At least she had
the conscience
to stand up and realize
what she'd done wrong...
which is more
than I can say for you.
I think it best that we...
now prepare
for our departure, Captain.
If you don't mind, I'd like
to go to your Sick Bay
to attend Jora Mirell.
I'm going to talk
to the Doctor.
I want to see you in my
ready room in one hour.
I know that I could have found
a better way
to handle the situation
than just charging
into the mess hall
like that.
I was just too angry
to think straight.
Not the first time
that's happened, I know,
but if you had seen
what I saw...
I might have done
exactly the same thing.
You believe me.
I believe that the memories
you experienced were real.
Then we've got to do
something about it.
We have to make this public.
You tried that today.
They didn't want to listen.
Then we have to find proof.
Let me go down
to the planet.
There must be some evidence left
of what really happened.
Maybe there are
other people like Korenna
who might be willing
to tell the truth.
Whatever the Enarans
have done,
it's not our place
to bring them to justice.
If they've chosen to conceal
part of their history
from their own descendants,
that's their decision,
whether we approve
of it or not.
It's not just
a matter of history.
This could happen again
if no one knows
it happened before.
We simply have no right
to get involved.
Jora Mirell was murdered
on board this ship,
which gives us a reason
to investigate.
Maybe if we can expose
the reason why she was killed,
the Enarans will start
to ask questions.
I've gotten a full report
from the Doctor.
He specifically looked
for evidence
to support your
accusations.
He didn't find any.
They could have used
their telepathy somehow,
in some way that the Doctor
couldn't detect.
We have no basis for
a murder investigation.
I released her body
to the Enarans.
So that's it?
We just go on our merry way
and nobody ever has to take
any kind of responsibility?
I've canceled
our trade negotiations,
as well as shore leave.
We'll leave orbit as soon
as the Enarans are off the ship.
B'Elanna?
I believe the
Enaran engineers
are collecting the last
of their equipment right now.
If there's anything more
you'd like to say to...
any of them...
Thank you.
Thank you, Captain.
I'm relieving you.
Can we talk
for a minute?
I have nothing
to say to you.
Then just listen.
Like Harry said,
it couldn't hurt to do that.
I'm leaving soon.
I know you have
no reason to believe
what I've said
about your people.
All you have is my word
against everything
you've ever been taught.
That's right.
So prove me wrong.
Go down to Enara
and find the colony
where the Regressives
were supposed to live.
Talk to people.
Ask questions.
Learn the truth for yourself.
Let me tell you
about my experiences.
Maybe that will give you
someplace to start.
I wish...
I had your abilities.
I could just show you.
You would do that?
Share your experiences openly?
Of course.
Then you'd know
I'm telling you the truth.
I can make the connection
between us.
( tapping )
What took you so long?
( giggling )