JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
stardate 50063.2.
We've accepted an invitation
from the Nechani
to take a few days'
shore leave on their world.
We're enjoying the opportunity
to learn about their culture.
NECHANI MALE:
This sanctuary honors
our Ancestral Spirits.
Their presence
is very strong here.
Those are brothers
of the Nechisti Order.
They've devoted
their lives
to serving
the Spirits.
Here's something
you might find interesting.
What do you think
this means?
Hard to tell.
A fertility
symbol, maybe?
Or a blessing for
good luck or wisdom.
Or happiness and love.
Do you hear something?
What?
Look at that.
It's beautiful.
It looks like a shrine.
Come on, sweeting,
we don't want to
be left behind.
I just want to take
a quick look.
Kes!
Kes.
Can you hear me?
Help!
Somebody!
We need help!
TORRES:
What happened?
NECHANI:
Oh, you mustn't be here.
This shrine is protected.
She didn't touch anything.
She went as far as that archway
and then an energy field
knocked her down.
Torres to Voyager.
We have a medical emergency.
Beam Kes and Neelix
directly to Sick Bay.
MAN:
Yes, Lieutenant.
Oh, this is most unfortunate.
Please, I must ask you
to leave as well.
We aren't going anywhere
until we find out
what happened to her.
What kind of energy
was she exposed to?
I-I-I have no idea.
This is a sacred place.
Only the monks truly understand
what happens here.
Then we'll bring
scanning equipment down
and investigate
for ourselves.
That's out of the question.
It would show disrespect
to the Spirits.
One of our crew has
been critically injured.
We aren't going to stand
by and do nothing.
There's nothing you can do.
She's been punished
by the Spirits.
She's going to die.
If you prevent us
from helping Kes,
we will hold you
directly responsible
for anything
that happens to her.
I will make a full report
to our Captain.
I'm sure you'll be hearing
from her.
I'll be happy to talk to her
and to do
whatever I can to help,
but your presence here
only makes
a delicate situation worse.
Please, leave now.
Her life signs are
very weak but stable.
It appears that her
synaptic pathways
have undergone
a severe neuroleptic shock,
which is disrupting
all cortical functions.
It is similar to
a comatose state,
but with none of the usual
biochemical markers.
You can cure her,
can't you?
I can't even speculate
on a treatment
until I know more about
what caused her condition.
We're working on that.
We aren't allowed near the area
the accident occurred.
but Kim and Torres are scanning
the sanctuary from Voyager.
They'll report
their findings to you.
And I have an appointment
to talk to the magistrate.
I'm hoping he'll be able
to cut through some
of the restrictions
the monks have set up.
MAGISTRATE:
Excuse me, Captain...
I'd like to do
something to help.
The Nechani must have records.
Some kind of scientific data
on this energy field.
Go down to the planet
and see what you can find.
I'll be back soon.
Please understand, Captain,
I'm caught in a most
difficult situation.
I'm an official
of the government
not a spiritual leader.
I don't pretend
to understand
why the Spirits do
what they do.
Then perhaps I could
talk with the brothers.
I've asked
the Nechisti Council
to give you an audience,
but I'm afraid they consider
the matter closed.
They've asked me to express
their sympathies for your loss.
There is no loss
at this point.
Kes is still alive.
Surely, there's some
way to treat her.
Can't you insist that
the monks meet with me?
We have an agreement
with the Council.
They don't involve
themselves with government
and we don't interfere
in their spiritual matters.
It's been that way for
centuries and it's always
worked well for us.
Then can you tell me
what you do know
about the sanctuary
and what happens there?
I'll try.
That particular shrine
is where the monks go
to receive the gift
of purification--
cleansing of the soul.
It is one of our
most holy places.
You mean the monks can enter it
without being harmed?
They prepare themselves
with a sacred ritual
during which they speak directly
with the Ancestral Spirits.
After that, they are able
to enter the shrine safely.
What happens in that ritual?
How does it offer protection
against the energy field?
Captain, you seem to want
explanations for everything.
I don't have them.
Only the brothers who've
gone through the ritual
know what happens there,
and they're sworn to secrecy.
The energy field
that Kes encountered--
is there anyone
who could give me
scientific information
that would help us analyze it?
All we know is that it is a
naturally occurring phenomenon.
If you're telling me...
that there's nothing
you can do to help Kes,
I simply won't accept that.
If I could help you, I would.
I swear it.
I blame myself.
If I'd watched more carefully,
seen that she was approaching
the shrine...
There's nothing more
to be done now.
You have our sympathy.
Have Kim and Torres
given you a report?
Yes. I received
a fascinating lesson
in the challenges of getting
clear scanner readings
through solid rock.
We were eventually able
to distinguish
an intense biogenic field
at the site of Kes's accident.
That would certainly explain
the neuroleptic shock.
She was lucky not to have
been killed instantly.
As I understand it,
the Nechani monks
are able to enter the field
without being harmed at all.
Really? I don't expect
they'd care to tell us how?
No, they wouldn't.
( door opens )
She's not responding
to conventional treatments
and frankly, I'm running out of
unconventional ideas as well.
The level of activity
in her brain is so low,
I can't rule out
the possibility
of permanent damage,
even if I can revive her.
The longer she stays
in this condition,
the less likely it is
she'll ever recover.
How is she?
I'm afraid there's
been no change.
I've researched
everything I could find
about the sacred shrine.
I didn't uncover
much scientific evidence,
but there was one story--
it was in a very old text,
I'm not sure how reliable--
about a boy who recovered
from a condition like Kes's.
He was a young prince.
He wandered into
the shrine accidentally
and he went into
a death sleep.
Everyone said it was
the will of the Spirits.
His father, King Nevad,
refused to accept that,
so he went through
the ritual
to seek an audience
with the Spirits
and he pleaded
for his son's life.
The Spirits,
in their infinite mercy,
granted his request.
That was the only trace
of hope that I could find.
Maybe it's enough.
Well, you've certainly done
your research, Captain.
I'm familiar with the story.
I heard it as a child.
It suggests that there's
still a chance for Kes.
MAGISTRATE:
You're talking
about a very specific case.
Nevad was able to claim
responsibility for the prince,
as a father and as a king.
That's why the Spirits
were willing to listen to him.
The Captain of a starship
is fully responsible
for every member of her crew.
( sighs )
So she is.
Then on that basis,
I'd like to go through
the ritual myself.
I haven't heard
from the magistrate yet,
but he seemed to think
there was a strong possibility
the monks would let me
go through the ritual.
Captain, forgive me,
but you've never been
one to put much trust
in religious ceremonies.
Exactly what is it
you hope to accomplish?
If you're asking
whether I expect to speak
to the Ancestral Spirits--
no, of course not.
But something happens
to the monks
when they go through the ritual,
something that allows them
to withstand the effects
of the biogenic field.
I want to find out what that is.
It might provide clues
to a treatment.
Some kind of physiological
change, maybe.
That's what I'm guessing.
The shamans of the Karis Tribe
on Delios VII practice a ritual
that increases the electrical
resistance of their skin.
It protects them
from plasma discharges
in their sacred caves.
Something similar must happen
during this ritual.
We'll have to find a way
to allow the doctor
to monitor
your physical condition,
and you should have a way to
call for an emergency beam-out
if you need it,
as a precaution.
We don't have any idea
what the ritual entails.
I've been reviewing the
Federation's cultural database.
Most traditional
spirit quest ceremonies
involve some kind
of physical challenge
or a test of endurance--
to prove the mastery
of spirit over body.
My instinct tells me
this one will be similar.
A series of ordeals that will
result in biochemical changes.
Of course, there's always
the possibility
that the Ancestral Spirits
really do control
what happens
in the shrine.
To each his own, Commander.
But I imagine if we
scratched deep enough,
we'd find a scientific basis
for most religious doctrines.
I remember when my mother
taught me about the science
underlying the vision quest.
In a way I felt... disappointed.
Some of the mystery was gone.
Maybe the Nechani have chosen
not to lose the mystery.
Under other circumstances,
I'd be more than happy
to go along with their choice.
Right now, it's killing
one of my crew.
KIM:
Bridge to the Captain.
Janeway here.
You have
an incoming transmission
from the magistrate.
Put it through
to Chakotay's office.
Aye, Captain.
I must congratulate you,
Captain.
Your creative approach
to this problem
has fascinated
the Nechisti Council.
Then they've approved
my request?
Eagerly.
They consider it an honor
that you want to seek
the Spirits.
The ritual traditionally
begins at sunset.
A guide will meet you at
the entrance to the sanctuary.
Thank you.
I appreciate your efforts.
I have been greatly troubled
by your misfortune, Captain.
If you are able
to convince the Spirits
to spare your friend,
no one would be happier than I.
Everything seems to be working.
The subdermal bioprobe
will transmit any changes
in your biochemistry.
KIM:
And, Captain,
the implant also
contains a homing beacon,
which we'll be able to pick up
no matter how far into the
sanctuary you go.
Just tap it
like a combadge,
and we'll transport
you immediately.
Thank you both.
I don't think
that will be necessary.
It is standard procedure
to carry arms
on an away mission,
particularly when you
don't know what to expect.
This is strictly an
information-gathering mission.
I don't want to appear hostile.
Energize.
( buzzing )
( tapping )
( chuckling )
I don't suppose
you know anything
about chromodynamic lights?
No, not really.
Oh...
I suppose I could look at it.
They're as fussy
as Tarchee cats.
You tune them too high,
they burn out.
You tune them too low,
they sputter.
I've told the monks
to replace them all
with neodyne lights.
It would save hours
of repair work.
That device you've got,
what is that?
It's called a tricorder.
A tricor...
What exactly does
a tricorder do?
It's a scanning device.
Interesting. May I?
Oh. Atmospheric reading,
energy field analysis,
full technical database.
This is certainly
a convenient thing to have.
Oh, I didn't mean
for you to keep it.
I'll need that back.
( chuckling ):
Ah...
No, you won't.
You're my guide.
Guide, advisor,
spiritual companion--
whatever term you prefer
is fine with me.
Well, why didn't you say
something earlier?
Shall we get started?
It's all right,
Kathryn.
Would it be breaking
any vows of secrecy now
to tell me what this ritual
will involve?
Why do you think I know?
Haven't you been through
this before?
Don't worry.
I'll help you
find your way.
Tell me--
have you completely
committed yourself
to this journey?
Yes.
You're willing
to go through
what the monks have
been doing for centuries
to help them find
the Spirits?
Yes.
So you can send
biochemical data
back to your ship?
No, it wasn't magic.
Our bio-scanners
detected the microprobe
under your skin.
I hope that won't be a problem.
Makes no difference
at all.
You are fond of your little
devices, aren't you?
They've always served me well.
I'm sure they have.
Please, come this way.
Who are you?
I'm Kathryn Janeway.
Is this where
the ritual begins?
Oh, the ritual... yes.
We're waiting.
Come, join us.
What exactly
are you waiting for?
Just... waiting.
How long have you been
sitting here?
Uh, how long has it been?
Why are you asking me?! I've
lost track!
It's been a while.
I know that.
Oh, it's been...
as long as we can remember.
Are you telling me
I have to wait a lifetime
before I can go
through the ritual?
I didn't hear anyone
say that, did you?
Certainly not, all we said
was that we're waiting.
I'm just trying to understand
how this works.
The monks I saw
in the sanctuary were young.
They couldn't have waited
such a long time
to go through their rituals.
Now, she's right
about that, you know.
She's a smart one.
She thinks she is,
at any rate.
This is a test of some kind,
isn't it?
To prove my determination.
A test? She thinks
we're a test.
What is she
talking about?
She must like tests.
I suppose tests
make sense to her.
Has anyone ever tried
to open this door?
How many times
do we have to tell you
that we are waiting?!
My dear, why don't
you just sit down and relax?
You're much too tense.
You're welcome
to wait with us.
I don't want to wait. I have
a friend who's depending on me.
I have to go through
the ritual.
I wonder if she's
always this impatient!
Oh, she's just
determined.
She wants to get on with it.
Seems to me, she
could be friendly
and sit for
a few minutes.
No, no. She knows
what she wants to do.
She's not the kind
to sit around
when she has a mission
to accomplish.
( sighs )
I told you.
I told you
it was locked.
( banging on door )
Yes?
I mean no disrespect.
But unless
there's something
I'm supposed
to accomplish here,
I'd like to continue
with the ritual.
By all means.
I'm not sure
how to begin.
Do you want me to give
you orders, Captain?
I'll do whatever
you ask of me.
I see.
So you think that
this is just a matter
of doing what
you're told.
No, I'm sure there is
spiritual significance
behind the challenges
involved.
Challenges?
That's what you expect.
I don't have any idea
what to expect.
I've studied a number
of ritualistic societies
and many of the rites
have commonalities.
This one may be
completely different.
I'm willing to do
whatever is necessary.
I don't doubt that.
But do you realize that all
of this is meaningless?
That the only thing
that matters
is finding your connection
to the Spirits?
I'm going to make
every effort to do that,
but I didn't come here
for personal enlightenment.
I'm trying to save
a member of my crew.
That's a worthy cause.
I hope the Spirits
listen to you.
Then let's begin.
The first challenge.
Stand like this.
Hold that.
Mmm.
Now...
what do you see
in your hands?
I see... a stone.
Keep looking.
DOCTOR:
Her respiration and pulse
have remained steady.
But there's been a gradual
buildup of lactic acid
in her extensor muscles
over the last hour.
What does that mean?
Is she in danger?
Not at all.
She's probably experiencing
light strain.
What you'd expect
in an endurance ritual.
Then there's nothing
so far
that would suggest
a treatment for Kes?
It's too early to tell.
I'm downloading
every iota of information
from the bioprobe sensors
into a physiometric program,
which is analyzing the data.
Even the smallest
physiological change
may prove significant.
We can't discount anything.
What do you see now?
I still see... a stone.
I guess you're not going to tell
me what I'm supposed to draw.
That would be too easy,
wouldn't it?
It's up to you--
draw whatever feels right.
I've never been
able to draw.
My sister was the artist
in the family.
And you were the scientist.
It's true.
When other children
were outside playing games,
I was doing
mathematics problems.
Mathematics? I can see
why you enjoyed it.
Solve a problem,
get an answer.
The answer's either
right or wrong.
It's very absolute.
I've always found that
satisfying.
I'm sure you did.
What did you see?
I'm not sure.
Describe it.
Aha.
What?!
What is it?!
What have you found?
There have been
significant increases
in the Captain's
respiration, neuropeptides
and adenosine
triphosphate levels.
Is that bad?
It certainly suggests
she's going through
a grueling physical
experience.
But it's the neuropeptides
that are interesting.
The saturations have risen
to quite an abnormal level.
Is that good or bad?
I can't say it's either, so far
as the Captain is concerned.
But it certainly seems
a substantial piece
of information.
Neuropeptide levels this high
could well create a natural
barrier to biogenic energy.
So you have something
that will help Kes.
Not yet, but it's
the first piece of data
that allows me even
to formulate a hypothesis.
It should be me going
through all that.
I was the one who let Kes
get hurt in the first place.
Mr. Neelix, you're wallowing.
I'm...
Wallowing in useless remorse.
I'll have to ask you to stop.
It's bad for the patient.
It's just frustrating
to be so helpless.
If it's any consolation,
Mr. Neelix,
I do understand.
I'm exhausted.
Oh, thank you.
Your microprobe
should be transmitting
all kinds of interesting
information back to the ship.
( hissing )
What is that?
It's a nesset.
They're able to travel
from this world
into the spirit realm.
They serve as gatekeepers.
Gatekeepers.
Then I'm ready to enter
the spirit realm.
Do you think you're ready?
Yes, I do.
Then you are.
Go ahead.
Put your hand in.
( hissing )
( squealing )
We can stop right now
if you like.
No, I'm not quitting.
( hissing )
( sharp twang )
( gasping )
Don't be afraid.
Oh... it's burning me!
Oh, my chest!
Getting tight!
( panting ):
Oh, oh, oh...
Kes:
Captain?
Kathryn?
I'm dying.
Everyone dies
eventually.
It's been three days
since she had any sleep.
How long are we going
to let her go through this?
I understand your concern,
but I must point out
that her vital signs are stable.
She seems to be
in no immediate danger.
She's been poisoned
with some unknown toxin.
It may be having an effect
we can't gauge.
It could lie dormant
for a few days
and then suddenly fluctuate
and kill her in minutes.
You seem to be implying that
I'm not paying attention.
I assure you, I am
monitoring her constantly.
If I thought she were
in jeopardy, I would act.
Doctor, is there anything
which might be preventing her
from using the homing signal
in her implant?
Not that I'm aware of.
She's fully conscious
and has complete motor control.
If she wanted to transport,
she could signal us.
Are you getting enough
meaningful information
to justify
her continuing this ordeal?
I am getting
some remarkable data.
Her entire biochemistry
is undergoing a series
of unique interactions. Look.
This amino acid
has been formed
as a result of the breakdown
of the toxin
in her bloodstream.
It's affecting the normal flow
of neurotransmitters
and very likely having
a hallucinogenic effect.
Is she delusional?
I think she's experiencing
the Nechani version
of a psychoactive drug.
Then is it possible
she's in no condition
to activate the homing signal?
I don't believe that's the case
and I strongly suspect
this biochemical change
is going to give us
the answers we need.
The toxin in her bloodstream
may very well be the key
to creating a treatment for Kes.
Commander, the decision
is ultimately yours, of course.
However, I believe it would
be the Captain's desire
to complete the ritual.
All right. We'll leave
her there for now.
But I'm not moving from this
monitor until she gets back.
Oh.
( rustling )
What is this?
An hallucination?
I'm only here
to serve as a voice--
an interpreter
for the Ancestral Spirits.
I see.
If there are
other beings here,
could I see them myself?
You mean you want proof
that we exist?
That would be helpful.
It's irrelevant.
I don't want to be
disrespectful.
I have gone through
every part of the ritual
that I have been asked to.
Everything you've gone through
is meaningless.
You've been told that.
I know.
I just want to bring this
to completion--
to make my request.
Then, by all means, do so.
I cite the story
of King Nevad as precedent.
In the same way
he pleaded for his son,
I ask that Kes
be restored to health.
Your request
is inconsequential.
You have what you need
to save her yourself.
Welcome back.
How long?
Does that matter?
Oh...
I'd like to know.
39 hours.
You must take care of yourself.
Your body's weak.
I guess the physical
conditioning programs
on the holodeck didn't
quite prepare me for this.
Has it been worthwhile?
I think so.
I was told that I had
what I needed to save Kes.
Then it must be true.
The Spirits would not
deceive you.
Whenever you're ready.
Thank you.
You could use a good night's
sleep and a solid meal,
but otherwise,
you're in good shape.
When can you begin
treating Kes?
Right away.
The ritual may have been arduous
for you, Captain,
but it was certainly worthwhile.
As I suspected,
the toxin was the key.
That's what produces
the natural immunity
the Nechani monks acquire
before they enter
the biogenic field.
How does that translate
into a cure for Kes?
I've created
a physiometric program
to analyze the immune mechanism
and develop a treatment regimen.
Then let's get started.
Captain,
if you'll excuse me.
I'm probably more useful
on the Bridge right now.
I'll carry out
the treatment in stages
to reduce the physical stress
from the metabolic changes.
( beeping )
What's that?
Is something wrong?
I don't believe so.
( beeping continues )
Hmm. Her electrolyte balance
is deviating,
but that's not entirely
unexpected.
It isn't.
Hmm...
What does that mean--
"hmm" what?
Mr. Neelix, if you keep on
pestering me with questions,
I won't be able to concentrate
on what I'm doing.
( siren-like beep )
( beeping continues )
Something is wrong.
What is it, doctor?
Her cardiac functions
are being disrupted.
I don't understand it.
Lectrazine should counteract
the disruptions.
( beeping continues )
This is baffling.
Her biochemical levels
are exactly what they need to be
to correct the damage.
She should be awake and alert.
Then why isn't she?!
I can't explain it.
Her vital signs are unstable.
I have to discontinue treatment.
I don't understand it.
Can't we try again?
It's too dangerous.
Do you have
any other options?
No. I'm sorry, Captain,
but it appears that everything
you went through...
was meaningless.
You meant what you said,
didn't you?
Everything I went
through was meaningless.
Yes.
I did everything
you asked of me.
You led me to believe that
would allow me to help Kes.
I haven't led you anywhere,
Kathryn.
You've taken me along
wherever you wanted to go.
This was your ritual.
You set these challenges
for yourself.
It's true that I came here
with certain expectations...
Are you saying
that you simply...
fulfilled my expectations?
You'd have settled
for nothing else.
I'm not ready to give up.
If there's still a way
to save Kes, I want to try.
You've come back
to seek the Spirits.
I don't know what I'm seeking.
Then I believe
you are ready to begin.
Well. Look
who's come back.
So, your little adventure
didn't quite work out
the way you'd
planned it.
You put yourself through
a lot of trouble
and for nothing, didn't you?
Don't feel bad.
You wouldn't believe
some of the things
people have done to themselves
on their way
to seek the Spirits.
So there's no real ritual
after all.
"Real" is such a relative term.
Most of the challenges in life
are the ones we create
for ourselves.
And you are particularly hard
on yourself, aren't you?
I've always been driven
to succeed.
Stubborn, I'd say.
You didn't really consider
sitting and waiting
with us, did you?
Well, I'm here now,
and I'm asking for your help.
I want to understand the purpose
of waiting
in this room.
But isn't it enough
to sit and be sociable?
We're good company.
That's what I'm supposed to do--
talk to the Ancestral Spirits.
Oh...
first, we were a test,
and now we're
the Ancestral Spirits.
Are you?
That would be nice
and quantifiable for you,
wouldn't it?
If the Spirits
were something
that you could see
and touch and scan
with your little devices.
If you can explain everything,
what's left to believe in?
I know it's an important part
of your religion
to trust the Spirits
without question,
but I wasn't brought up
that way.
It's hard for me to accept.
So much for your tolerant,
open-minded Starfleet ideals.
There's a difference
between respecting
the spiritual beliefs
of other cultures
and embracing them myself.
Fine.
Don't embrace a thing.
It's all
the same to us.
Go on back
to your ship
and play with your
molecular microscanner.
WOMAN:
You've tried
all that already,
but it didn't work,
did it?
Kes didn't get better.
No, she didn't.
Why not?
The doctor couldn't explain it.
So it's inexplicable.
A miraculous nonrecovery.
We haven't found the reason yet.
But of course you will.
You'll find all
the answers eventually
with enough time
and study
and the right
sort of tools.
That's what you believe,
isn't it, as a scientist?
Be honest.
Yes, that's what
I've always believed.
Even when her science fails
right before her eyes,
she still has
full confidence in it.
Now there's a leap of faith.
Unconditional trust.
Now that's promising.
All right...
if you're saying that science
won't help Kes,
what will?
You won't like it.
I'm willing to do
whatever's necessary.
Kill her.
She's as good as dead already.
Finish the job.
Give her another jolt of that--
what do you call it?--
biogenic field.
Oh... that would do it.
It would do what exactly?
There you go again.
Always looking
for a rational explanation.
Well, there isn't one.
Your orbital scans
and medical research
have given you the facts...
and they tell you
the biogenic field is lethal.
If you believe the facts.
Let all of that go, Kathryn.
Take Kes back into the shrine
and trust the Spirits
to return her soul.
The ritual I went through
was meaningless...
and Kes has done nothing
to prepare herself.
How could either of us be ready
to go through the field?
If you believe you're ready,
then you are.
There's no more to it
than that.
But if you go in with any doubt,
with any hesitation,
then you're both dead.
So, what are you going
to do, Captain?
You know I won't stand by
and watch Kes die
if there's anything
I can do to save her.
I want to believe it's possible.
I'm going to try.
Janeway to Chakotay.
Captain, we've been worried
about you.
I'm all right.
I want you to beam Kes
down here to the sanctuary.
Acknowledged.
I'll bring her down myself.
Chakotay to Sick Bay.
Doctor, prepare Kes
for transport.
DOCTOR:
Understood.
( whoosh of active transport)
The doctor says her life signs
are deteriorating.
He almost wouldn't let us
take her out of Sick Bay.
You've found a
way to help her.
Yes, I have.
I'm taking her back
into the biogenic field.
I hate to question you,
Captain, but why?
I believe it will save her life.
You have some new information
on the effects of the field?
I can't explain it to you.
Captain... you've been through
a lot in the past few days.
I know what I'm doing.
Are you sure of that?
There are 800 megajoules
of biogenic energy running
through that shrine.
The thoron radiation levels
are off the scale.
That's what you'd be taking
her and yourself into.
Why don't you take some
time to think about this
and let us run
a few more scans?
No.
Captain...
this isn't like you.
You know you'll always have
my gratitude
for everything you've done
to save Kes,
but I couldn't--
and I know she couldn't--
ask you to risk your own life
like this.
There are too many other people
who need you.
He's right.
It's my responsibility
to keep you safe--
for the crew's sake,
if not for your own.
I'd rather not have
to relieve you of duty,
but if your judgment's
been impaired in any way...
He can't really
do that, can he?
Yes, he can.
I suppose it might
be necessary
if the Captain of a ship
were really mentally impaired,
but you're not crazy, Kathryn.
You know that.
NEELIX:
These are the same people
who were willing
to let Kes die just for
disturbing their shrine.
Can you take their word for it
that you'll be
safe in there?
I can't give you
my word on that.
Nobody knows what
will happen to them
in the shrine
until they go in.
I don't know the answers...
but you do.
Captain...
I don't understand this.
Neither do I.
That's the challenge.
Kes...
( sighs )
The tricorder readings Commander
Chakotay took at the shrine
reveal traces of iridium ions,
which we could've
known about sooner
if we'd been permitted
to take those readings at first.
And iridium ions
are significant?
They caused a temporary
dielectric effect
in the outer epidermal layers,
which neutralized
some of the biogenic energy--
not much, but enough to make the
Captain's altered biochemistry
an effective defense.
Then how was I cured?
The metabolic treatment
I administered
protected you against the full
impact of exposure to the field
when the Captain
took you through.
That exposure functioned like
a natural cortical stimulator
and reactivated
your synaptic pathways.
KES:
That's fascinating, doctor.
Captain?
If there's something
about my analysis
you disagree with...
It's a perfectly sound
explanation, doctor.
Very... scientific.