MAN:
There was another
anti-war demonstration
at the UC-Santa Cruz campus
last night.
Tear gas was used
to disperse the crowd
of 3,000 angry students.
The temperature right now in
downtown Barstow is 75 degrees.
( rock music playing )
( static interference )
( hissing )
Far out.
( door beeping )
Come in.
Sorry, Tuvok.
I was just practicing
my serve.
Your "serve?"
Tennis.
After 19 years, I've decided
to take it up again.
I'm a little rusty.
I played in a novice tournament
on the holodeck.
I lost my first match
in straight sets.
Perhaps if you maintained
eye contact with the ball
at the apex of its trajectory
your serve would be
more effective.
You play tennis?
Simple physics, captain.
Not as simple as
when I played
on the high school
tennis team.
What can I do
for you, Tuvok?
I've completed my monthly
security evaluation.
All systems and crew are...
CHAKOTAY:
Red alert.
Captain Janeway to the bridge.
Report.
CHAKOTAY:
Some sort
of spatial rift.
It opened right
in front of us.
Analysis.
It's a distortion
in the space-time continuum.
But it's got
a graviton matrix.
It's being artificially
generated.
CHAKOTAY:
By whom?
Sensors can't
get inside.
The distortion field's
fluctuating.
Something's coming out.
TUVOK:
It appears to be
a small ship--
approximately six meters
in length.
Magnify.
Sensors are reading
one occupant-- human.
He is holding position
at the perimeter of the rift.
There's a subspace signature
emanating from the ship.
Captain...
it's Federation.
Hail them.
No response.
They appear
to be charging weapons.
Shields up.
Hail them again.
Shields are down.
Get us out of here.
Helm control is off-line.
He's firing some kind of
subatomic disruptor.
Return fire.
Full phasers.
No effect.
Voyager's molecular
structure is coming apart!
Tuvok, divert all available
power to the deflector.
Send out a high-energy
polaron pulse.
It might help to disrupt
his weapon.
Emitting deflector pulse...
now.
It's working.
We are being hailed.
On screen.
Starship Voyager,
I'm Captain Braxton
of the Federation
timeship Aeon.
I've come from
29th century Earth,
500 years into your future.
Please disengage
your deflector pulse.
Why are you firing
at us?
Your vessel is responsible
for a disaster in my century--
a temporal explosion
that will destroy
all of Earth's solar system.
I've come back in time
to prevent that occurrence.
My mission is your destruction.
You must not resist.
I'm going to need more
information before I allow...
Debris from your secondary hull
was found in the explosion.
Captain, I simply--
No time!
He's remodulating
the subatomic disruptor.
Our deflector is losing power.
It won't hold
much longer.
Captain, if he's telling
the truth...
I won't sacrifice
this ship and crew
based on a ten second
conversation.
I need proof.
It doesn't look like
we're going to get it.
Adjust our deflector to match
the frequency of his weapon.
Try to overload his emitter.
It seems
to be working.
His weapon is off-line and
his ship has been damaged.
The rift is destabilizing
and he's being pulled
back inside.
Reestablish helm control.
PARIS:
I'm trying, Captain,
but we seem to be caught in some
kind of graviton distortion.
We're being pulled in, too.
Status.
Primary systems
are coming back on-line.
The weapons grid and power
array took heavy damage.
The temporal rift is closed.
Where are we?
Home.
We just cut across
half the galaxy.
The rift must have
originated here.
Hail Starfleet command.
No response
on standard frequencies.
Curious.
I am picking up a multitude
of narrow band E.M. signals.
Let's hear.
( voices speaking
simultaneously )
WOMAN:
...with no commercial
interruption.
MAN:
...leave a message at the beep,
MAN 2:
Robertson takes a hard left--
MAN 3:
...Colts at
the 35 yard line--
MAN 4:
Breaker, breaker,
this is Charlie--
( rock music playing )
The question isn't
where we are.
It's when we are.
Mr. Kim?
According
to astrometric readings...
the year is 1996.
The late 20th century.
PARIS:
Captain, they had surveillance
satellites during this time.
Maintain a high orbit.
And modulate the shields
to scatter their radar.
We don't want
to alarm the natives.
What about
the timeship?
Is it here too?
There's no sign
of the vessel in orbit.
Scanning the planet's surface.
I am picking up low-frequency
subspace readings
emanating from
the northern hemisphere.
Subspace technology
shouldn't exist
for another
100 years or so.
Could be our friend
from the 29th century.
Localize it.
North American continent.
Pacific coast.
The City of Los Angeles.
We've got to go down there.
If it is Captain Braxton,
he's the key to all this
and at the moment,
his ship is the only way we have
of getting back
to our own century.
Chakotay, Tuvok, Paris,
you're with me.
Mr. Kim, you have the bridge.
Yes, Ma'am.
As I recall, Tom, you're
something of an aficionado
on 20th century America.
That's right.
What will we need to pass
as locals in this era?
Simple. Nice clothes,
fast car
and lots of money.
Hey, buddy,
look what you did.
Aww yeah!
Hey, come on.
Sorry, man.
We could have worn
our Starfleet uniforms.
I doubt if anyone
would have noticed.
JANEWAY:
The subspace readings
are coming from within
a hundred meter radius
of our position
but I can't
pinpoint the source.
I find it hard to believe
a ship from the 29th century
could've landed on this beach
without being noticed.
We have no idea
what kind of technology
they might have
in the future.
Maybe it's cloaked.
Let's spread out.
Tuvok, Paris
go check the shoreline.
Chakotay and I
will search the boardwalk.
Aye, captain.
Well, Kathryn,
you got us home.
Right place...
wrong time.
But it is good to be
back, nevertheless.
Maybe I should look up
a few ancestors.
As I recall, one of them
was a school teacher in Arizona.
I don't know what
my relatives were doing
this far back in history--
Coming through, sorry!
For all I know,
she could be
my great,
great, great...
great grandmother.
She does have your legs.
Have you ever been to Southern
California, Chakotay?
No.
After the Hermosa Quake
of 2047
this entire region sank
under 200 meters of water
it became one
of the world's
largest coral reefs,
home to thousands
of different
marine species.
Some... interesting species
in this century.
Subspace readings
are weaker here.
Let's head up
to the boardwalk.
Ah...the sun feels great.
Thermal
and ultraviolet radiation
are at hazardous levels.
Lighten up, Tuvok.
This was a great
time and place,
and you're getting
to see it firsthand.
Come on, take off
your shirt.
And risk dermal dysplasia?
No, thank you.
Vulcans--
deep down,
you're all a bunch
of hypochondriacs.
The readings are coming
from over there.
Ten meters.
There.
So much for the timeship.
There's no doubt
about it.
The subspace readings
are coming from him.
No way.
Way.
It's crap.
The component density is too low
the voltage variance
is out of spec,
and I don't even like the color.
But, mister...
we've got less than six months
before we introduce
the Hyperpro P.C.
And with a chip like
this driving it
we'll have to change
the name to "Edsel."
I gave your company
this contract
because you're the best
in the business...
next to us, of course.
Go home, Jim.
Lose some sleep over this.
I want a full report
middle of next week.
( Intercom buzzes )
What am I doing, Dave?
You're in a meeting, sir.
And?
And I know
I'm not supposed to interrupt
but there's a woman calling
on line three
from Griffith Observatory--
a Rain Robinson.
She says it's urgent.
Put her through.
Henry Starling.
Hi. I don't know
if you remember me.
I'm one of the astronomers
at the SETI lab you're funding.
We met at the Griffith
restoration party.
Yes, yes. What is it?
Okay. Well, it was
my understanding
you wanted to be notified
immediately
if I ever picked up
a gamma emission
that matched the frequency
profile you gave me.
Well... I did.
So... I am.
Are you certain?
Positive. I tracked
the emission, and guess what.
The source is in orbit.
It is right above us.
When did it show up?
Uh... according to the raw data
about 90 minutes ago.
I'm not picking up anything
from the standard
search parameters.
Wow. That means
no one else knows
there's something up there.
We have got to tell somebody
about this.
We've got to call NASA!
Rain, that's a little premature,
don't you think?
This could be a close encounter
but then again,
could be a flock of geese.
Hmm... geese
don't park themselves
20,000 kilometers
above North America.
Let's send a message up there,
see if there's a response.
No, no. We don't know
what we've found
and until we do, I'm not going
to risk embarrassing myself
or your observatory.
Track the emission,
collect more data
and keep me informed.
In the meantime,
I'm going to put
a bottle of champagne on ice.
Do you think E.T.
likes Chateau Coeur?
Well, if he doesn't, I've got
a six-pack in the fridge.
Good work, Rain.
Stay in touch.
Oh, what the hell.
( keyboard keys clacking )
Anyone up there?
That trip through the rift
is still affecting
our primary systems.
Weapons are off-line
we blew three
E.P.S. conduits
and our main transporter
buffer just crashed.
We've got an away team
down there.
I know. We've still got
emergency transporters
but they're short-range.
How close to the surface
would we have to get
to beam them up?
Pretty close-- I'd say less
than ten kilometers.
If we do that, somebody
is going to see us.
Sir, I'm picking up
an E.M. Signal
from the planet's surface.
It's directed
at our coordinates.
On screen.
MAN:
Greetings from
the people of Earth.
[RECORDINGS PLAYING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGES]
TORRES:
Shall I respond, sir?
Absolutely not.
JANEWAY:
He appears to live on
the street.
That pushcart seems to contain
all his belongings.
CHAKOTAY:
From what we can tell,
he spends most of his time
putting up literature
about the end of the world.
( beeping )
Hello?
MAN:
Janeway here.
Captain, we've got a problem.
We received a signal
from the surface.
It looks like
a standard greeting
designed for
extraterrestrials.
We've been detected.
It looks that way.
We tracked the signal
to an observatory
about 20 kilometers
from your location.
Transport Paris and Tuvok
to those coordinates.
I can't do that right now,
not without going
into a lower orbit.
The main pattern buffer
is off-line.
B'elanna says it could take
a couple of days to repair.
In that case,
transmit those coordinates
to Mister Tuvok's tricorder.
He and Tom will have
to get there using more...
conventional means.
Aye, Captain. Kim out.
Nobody walks in Los Angeles, and
they don't have
much of a public
transportation system.
We're going to need some wheels.
Do what you have to do.
Find out who sent that message
and get more information
have we been detected?
How many people know about us?
We cannot risk
contaminating the time-line.
Aye, captain.
See you later.
Who the hell are you?!
This is my stuff!
It's all right.
We don't want your stuff.
We just want to ask you
a few questions.
No! No, no, no!
No more questions!
No. No more surveys!
Damn social workers
coming around all the time!
No, I don't need your advice!
I don't need your...
Voyager...
Oh, I knew you'd show up.
This is all your fault.
This is all your doing!
Captain Braxton?
I told you to turn off
your deflector pulse
but you wouldn't
listen to me!
Voyager! Fools!
Captain,
what's happened to you?
The last time
we saw you...
I was a younger man,
confident in my mission!
But you wouldn't listen to me.
No.
You were too concerned
with yourselves.
You were trying
to destroy us.
I was trying to save
billions of lives--
to stop a chain of reaction
that started with Voyager.
It's too late now.
All things are set in motion.
The temporal explosion
will occur.
The end is coming!
The future's end!
Captain, how long
have you been here--
in the 20th century?
Oh, too long.
30 years too long.
And yet we just
arrived. Why?
Pure chance.
When you knocked
my navigation system off course.
There's no telling
where we would have ended up.
Who's been here?
Who took my pencils?
Oh! Always
something missing.
People always trying
to steal things.
Greedy people!
Post-industrial barbarians!
JANEWAY:
Captain,
we want to help you
but you've got to give us
more information.
You said that Voyager
causes the explosion.
Yes.
No...
and yes.
That's a paradox, my dear.
"A" leads to "B"
leads to "C" leads to "A".
Juvenile minds.
Oh, how can I
make you understand, huh?
A... There's an explosion
in the 29th century.
Debris from Voyager's hull
is found in evidence.
I go back in time
to destroy you.
B... You try to stop me,
disabling my weapon
which causes me to crash land
back here in the 20th century.
C... Someone in this century
steals my timeship
and launches it.
They go into the future
and once there
they make one critical mistake
which causes
a temporal explosion
that takes us
all the way back to "A."
There's an explosion
in the 29th century.
The cycle of causality
is complete.
How do you know all this?
What evidence do you have
that it will be your timeship
that causes
the disaster?
I've spent 30 years
answering that very question.
Ah, yes. When the explosion
first happened,
my sensors recorded
a whole variety
of chronometric data.
The pulses were highly chaotic.
At first, I thought it was
a warp-core implosion,
but then I found debris
from Voyager,
and my theory seemed to be
confirmed. It was you.
But then someone here
stole my timeship.
Then it started to dawn on me.
If someone were to fly
my timeship into the future
without recalibrating
the temporal matrix
then that could cause
the kind of explosion
that I witnessed
in the 29th century.
So it really wasn't
Voyager after all.
No. No, no, I reconstructed
all the chronometric data
as best I could remember it
and it proved
that I was right.
My ship causes the catastrophe.
Which raises the question
who has your timeship?
Starling.
Henry Starling, C.E.O.
Chronowerx Industries.
Philanthropist, entrepreneur,
outstanding citizen. Ha!
Before I crashed
in the year 1967
I made an emergency
beam-out, but he
found my ship
before I did
in some remote
mountain range.
I've been following
this corrupt
little man ever since
tracking his movements
but he's become
too powerful.
I can't get close to him.
Of course,
you can't accomplish anything
in this wretched century.
Nobody here listens.
Do you know that once
they put me
in a mental institution
and filled me
with primitive pharmaceuticals?!
Maybe we can help you find
Starling and your ship
and get us back
to where we belong.
No, I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
Why not?
Haven't you been listening?
"A" leads to "B"--
Leads to "C".
Yes we heard you.
Why shouldn't we try
to stop Starling?
Because somehow you're
involved in the disaster.
That's why I found debris
from Voyager's hull
at the explosion.
You will be destroyed as well.
Now that we know
what's going to happen
maybe we
can figure out...
POLICEMAN:
Hey, captain.
How you doing?
I understand
you been putting
these signs up
around the city again.
No. No, no, no.
Not me. I...
I would never do that.
Why don't you walk over here
and we can talk about it?
You stay right where you are.
You quasi-Cardassian
totalitarian!
No need to get upset.
We just want to talk
to you about the signs.
Now, there've been
a few people complaining.
Captain... tell
them I'm not crazy.
Tell them
I'm from the future.
They came from the
future, too, you know.
Okay.
Yeah, they came
in on a starship.
All right.
Traitors!
This is 247 Baker
in foot pursuit
of a 51-50 suspect.
We'll have to worry
about him later.
Right now,
we've got to find Starling.
We're not quite at
the little green men stage yet,
but believe me,
you'll be the first to know.
What I think we have here
is an overenthusiastic
young lady.
I'm afraid she's exaggerating.
We don't have anything.
Not yet.
Thank you, professor.
You know what
that little brat did?
She e-mailed a friend
of hers at J.P.L.
Who called his professor
at Cal Tech.
She's a security risk.
Go to Griffith, get the data,
get rid of her.
Yes, sir.
Dunbar.
If it's true--
if they're here--
it's only
a matter of time
before they find me.
There's no telling what
capabilities they'll have.
You may have
to use the weapon.
I understand.
TUVOK:
Perhaps we should find
a more secluded parking place.
This is, after all,
a stolen vehicle.
PARIS:
Nobody's around, Tuvok.
We're fine.
A taxicab would have been less
worrisome and more ethical.
PARIS:
We haven't stolen anything.
We borrowed a car, and we'll
return it to the dealership
as soon as we're done.
TUVOK:
I was referring to
the ethics of time travel.
PARIS:
Somehow, I doubt
that taking a test drive
is going to alter
the course of the universe.
Over here.
These are
radio wave readouts.
Looks like radio
telescope transmissions.
Pretty basic.
Lieutenant, you
are being careless.
Tuvok...
I will not lighten up on
this matter.
Thus far, I have tolerated
your impulsive methods.
At times, they do
work to our advantage
but discretion
is also a virtue.
We must leave things
exactly as they were.
( sighs )
They've found us,
all right.
The orbital schematic
matches Voyager's position.
According to this data,
they are tracking
the warp emissions
from our engines.
Nobody in this century
even knows
what warp emissions are.
Nevertheless,
it appears
they've configured their
telescope to scan for them.
Excuse me.
"do not enter",
"employees only"--
the sign on the door?
Uh, I'm sorry.
I think
we're a little lost.
We were on the museum tour,
and we took a wrong turn
at the Saturn exhibit.
Perhaps you could tell us
how to get back to the lobby.
Go back down the hall,
take a left at Mars
right at Halley's comet
and then just keep going
straight ahead
past the soda machine, okay?
This lab is, uh...
pretty groovy.
Groovy...
What do you do here?
We watch the skies.
For what?
Signs of extraterrestrial life.
Nice meeting you.
My name is Tom Paris,
by the way.
Rain Robinson.
Your curves don't
look so great.
Excuse me?
This is a Fourier
spectral analysis?
That's exactly
what it is.
You know, you might get
better resolution
if you adjust
your amplitude parameters.
You're probably right.
Or you might try using
a theta-band filter.
You know a lot
for someone
who can't find his way
past Saturn.
I majored in
astrophysics.
Where?
Starfleet academy.
Never heard of it.
Uh, east coast school.
Orgy of the Walking Dead?!
That's a classic!
Did you see the sequel, uh...
Bride of the Corpse?
Let me guess.
You minored
in "B" movies.
Something like that.
Pardon me, Tom.
We should be going.
Our friends
are waiting for us.
Yeah, right.
Got to go.
Hey.
Uh...
I do the planetarium show
Tuesday nights
so, uh...
you guys should come by
check it out bring your
friends...
"the best stars in Hollywood
are right above us."
Yeah, great...
but, I think we're
busy on Tuesday.
Thanks anyway.
No problem.
Whoa.
I downloaded all of her data
into the tricorder.
And disrupted her
data storage device.
Good. I hope she doesn't get
in any trouble.
It will simply look like
a computer malfunction.
It's a shame though.
She was about to make
the biggest discovery
in human history.
It could have changed
her career.
And ended ours.
I am curious,
Lieutenant.
What does it mean--
"groovy"?
Hey, hey, you guys!
Red alert!
Hey!
Just wait a minute.
What the hell
did you do to my computer?
It is screwed up.
The hard drive
is wiped.
Look, I don't have time
to explain.
Who are you people, and what is
that thing in your pants?
I beg your pardon?
ROBINSON:
That little gadget
you put in your pocket.
What is it,
a demagnetizer?
Get down!
What the hell?!
Do you have a car?
Yeah, over there.
We will need to use it.
Here!
KIM:
Operation officer's log
supplemental.
We've been on full sensor alert
looking for signs
that anyone else
has detected Voyager.
As a precaution,
I've also asked Neelix and Kes
to monitor all media
broadcasts.
We've set up a
computer algorithm
to search for key
words and phrases--
anything that might
indicate Voyager.
Anything so far?
Not yet. Although
we have come across
some very intriguing
televised broadcasts.
Take a look at this.
It's a form of entertainment
called a soap opera.
The exploration of human
relationships is fascinating.
Hmm. I can't imagine
just watching the story
and not being
a part of it.
That's because you've been
spoiled by the holodeck.
There's something
to be said
for noninteractive stories
like this--
being swept away
in the narrative.
Oh, I can't wait to see
if Blaine's twin brother
is the father
of Jessica's baby.
Good work.
Keep me informed
and don't get
too swept away.
Uh, I shall.
WOMAN:
Nobody will know
the difference.
BLAINE:
I'll know, Sharon.
He's my brother.
How can I face him
knowing that our son
is his son?
WOMAN:
All you need to know Jack,
is that I love you.
So far, so good.
We haven't set off
any alarms.
Our Mr. Starling has built
quite a corporate empire.
Looks like he's got
wealth, celebrity...
and an ego to match.
I see you never
learned to type.
Turn-of-the-millennium
technology
wasn't a required course
at the academy.
This is like stone knives
and bearskins.
CHAKOTAY:
Well, this isn't.
I'm detecting
a force field.
I can't scan
beyond this wall.
I don't see an access port
or a control panel.
Maybe we can find something
in his computer.
He's got a massive
database here,
but it's protected by
an encryption sequence.
I'm going to try
interfacing my tricorder.
Looks like a series
of pictographs.
They must have used symbols
to represent the different
functions of the computer.
Let's see what Henry's
been up to all these years.
The transtaters
were disrupted
by that energy weapon.
Our communicators
are useless.
That means we
can't call the...
our friends.
What do we do now?
You're going to take
a right at the next light
and a left
at the taco stand
'cause you're taking me home
and you're not keeping
the van.
I am afraid that is not
possible, Miss Robinson.
Your life
may be in danger.
I'm going to pop this hatch
and I'm going to start screaming
until you tell me
what's going on.
Who are you?
What is that thing in orbit?
Why did that guy try to kill us?
PARIS:
I told you we're
secret agents.
I'm opening the hatch.
Look, we saved your life.
Isn't it obvious
we're on your side?
I'm standing up.
I'm taking a deep breath.
Rain you are not
going to scream!
I know you're frightened
and you've seen
some pretty strange things
but you have to trust me.
We're not going
to hurt you
and I will explain everything.
It's either that, or take your
chances with the guy who tried
to vaporize you!
The U.F.O.--
what is it?
It's a Soviet
spy satellite.
Part of a massive
K.G.B. operation.
We're trying
to stop it.
Soviet? The U.S.S.R.
broke up five years ago.
The K.G.B. doesn't even
exist anymore.
That's what they'd
like you to think.
Perhaps we've told her
enough for now.
What about you, Agent Tuvok?
What's up with those ears?
Thought I didn't notice?
I did.
What about your weapons?
What are they--lasers?
I'm sorry.
That information is classified,
and as for my ears,
they are a family trait.
He's very sensitive
about them.
Whatever.
We must find a way
to contact our... friends.
JANEWAY:
Incredible.
Starling's computer
designs were inspired
by technology
from the timeship.
He introduced the very first
isograted circuit in 1969
two years after Braxton's
ship crash-landed.
And every few years
there's been
an equally revolutionary
advance in computers
all from
Chronowerx Industries
all based on Starling's
crude understanding
of 29th century technology.
Are you thinking what
I'm thinking, Chakotay?
I wish I weren't.
The computer age of
the late 20th century...
shouldn't have happened.
But it did, and it's
part of our history
all because of
that timeship.
Look at this.
Gantry, power conduits,
telemetry consoles.
This looks like a design
for a launching bay.
Braxton was right. The ship's
going to be launched.
We've got to send these
schematics
to Voyager for analysis.
Janeway to Voyager.
Kim here, Captain.
We're in Starling's office.
I want you to establish
a com-link with my tricorder
and try to upload his
computer database.
Aye, Captain.
We'll need a few minutes
to reconfigure
to their binary system.
Acknowledged.
Let's see if we can find out
where the location
of that launch pad is.
You're really getting
the hang of this.
I'm a quick study.
You know, Captain, in a way,
Braxton was right.
If we hadn't fought him when
he tried to destroy Voyager,
he wouldn't have been
pulled back in time,
his ship wouldn't have
crash-landed on Earth,
and none of this
would have happened.
Time travel. Since
my first day in the job
as a Starfleet captain,
I swore I'd never
let myself get caught in
one of these
Godforsaken paradoxes.
The future is the past,
the past is the future.
It all gives me
a headache.
Hold on...this looks promising.
Try "timeship
security portal."
Maybe it's linked to some sort
of surveillance system.
An image of the launch bay
would give us a clue
to its location.
I see you've made yourself
at home.
Welcome to the 20th century.
I know who you are.
You're from the future.
I knew you'd come
back one day.
I detected your
vessel in orbit
and Mr. Dunbar
here had a run-in
with your friends.
You're here to
take the timeship.
Mr. Starling
you're about to cause
a terrible disaster
that will affect
the 29th century
an explosion that will cost
billions of lives.
We're here to stop you
from doing that.
What are you
talking about?
If you launch that ship
and travel to the future
it will destroy
Earth's solar system.
How do you know this?
Well, let's just say we talked
to the ship's previous owner.
He told us that
if its temporal matrix
isn't precisely calibrated
you'll trigger
a temporal explosion.
That ship shouldn't be here.
It belongs
to another century.
We have to take it back.
( beeping )
What's that?
It's a communication device.
Someone's trying
to contact me.
( beeping )
Answer it.
Janeway here.
Captain, we've established
the com-link.
Ready to upload on your signal.
Do it.
STARLING:
My database.
Stop, or I'll kill
your captain.
Who is this?
You've got five seconds.
Break the link.
Done.
What's
our transporter status?
The main pattern buffers
are still off-line.
We can try an emergency
transport from a lower orbit.
That's exactly
what the captain
ordered us not to do.
We'd be risking detection.
Harry, we can't worry about that
now. Their lives are in danger.
And if somebody
sees a starship
flying through the clouds?
The captain put you in charge.
It is your decision.
Helm, get a fix
on Chakotay and the Captain.
B'elanna, stand by
emergency transporters.
Get ready to beam them
directly to the bridge.
Take us down.
You've taken over 3,000
gigabytes of information
including my launch plan
but that's not going
to be a problem, Captain.
I'll make a few changes
to my travel itinerary.
You're not going
to stop me.
If you don't
give us that ship
we'll take it by force.
In case you haven't noticed,
I'm holding the gun.
Not for long.
I've got a starship in orbit
that could vaporize
this entire building
in the blink of an eye.
And you along with it.
If necessary.
Captain, you've got
some cojones.
Kill them!
Damn.
Maintain present altitude. Keep
us within transporter range.
Chakotay, see if you can disable
the force field
around that timeship.
B'elanna, prepare to lock on
to the timeship
and beam it to cargo bay two.
Ensign Kim, you have
an impeccable sense of timing.
Not bad for your first day
in the big chair.
The force field's down.
Sir! The timeship!
They're trying
to teleport the ship.
The matter stream
is remodulating.
He's disrupting
transport.
Yes.
( typing quickly )
Captain,
I don't understand how,
but he's using our
transporter beam as a downlink.
He's accessing
our main computer.
( laughing )
( typing furiously )
Every time I try
to disable his downlink,
he comes up with
a new command override.
Starling is using 29th-century
technology against us.
We may not be able to
keep up with him.
Inertial dampers
are off-line.
He's gotten into
our propulsion systems.
Disengage transporters.
Destabilizing matter stream.
Transporters off-line.
We've terminated
the downlink, Captain,
but he got at least 20%
of our main computer data files.
Get us back into orbit,
and I want a full damage--
Captain Janeway,
Henry Starling here.
This is Janeway.
U.S.S. Voyager--
Intrepid class.
Much bigger than I expected...
and much less advanced.
Says here your ship
was launched
in the year... 2371?
You're from the 24th century?
And here all this time,
I thought
you were from the 29th.
Looks like I have
the home-field advantage.
Ooh, what's this?
Oh, now this is interesting.
Damage reports
are coming in.
Some minor power fluctuations
in the impulse drive
and a few
burned-out circuits
in the main computer core.
Nothing we can't handle.
KES:
Sick bay to bridge.
Captain,
I can't find the doctor.
Is his program off-line?
No. His program is gone.
Where am I?
Who are you?
Welcome.
Captain, this is Neelix.
There's something
on the television
I think you should see.
It's a current-events program.
I asked Neelix
to monitor Earth broadcasts.
I'm transferring it
to the main viewer.
MALE NEWSCASTER:
Incredible footage
was caught just an hour ago
by a man using his camcorder
to tape a backyard barbeque.
The massive,
unidentifiable object
does not appear to be
a meteorite, weather balloon,
or satellite, and one
aviation expert we've spoken to
has stated that
it's definitely not
any kind of U.S. aircraft
currently in use.
We're awaiting investigation
by local authorites,
and we'll keep you updated
as news develops
on this incredible story.