NARRATOR:
Last time on
Star Trek Voyager...
I'm Captain Braxton of
the Federation timeship Aeon.
I've come from
29th-century Earth.
Why are you firing at us?
Your vessel
is responsible
for a disaster in my century,
a temporal explosion
that will destroy
all of Earth's solar system.
I've come back in time
to prevent that occurrence.
My mission is your destruction.
We seem to be caught in some
kind of graviton distortion.
We're being pulled in too.
I find it hard to believe
a ship from the 29th century
could've landed on this beach
without being noticed.
That ship shouldn't be here.
It belongs to another century.
We have to take it back.
No one else knows
there's something up there.
We've got to tell somebody
about this.
We've got to call NASA.
She's a security risk.
Go to Griffith,
get the data
get rid of her.
What the hell did you do
to my computer?
It is screwed up.
The hard drive is wiped.
Get down!
Starling is using
29th century technology
against us.
We may not be able
to keep up with him.
Yes.
He's accessing
our main computer.
Get us back into orbit--
STARLING:
Captain Janeway,
you're from the 24th century,
and here, all this time I
thought you were from the 29th.
Looks like I have
the home-field advantage.
NARRATOR:
And now the conclusion.
Let me guess.
Someone broke into
the van last night
while I was sleeping
tried to snatch
the stereo.
You bravely
fought them off
and now you're
repairing the damage.
That's exactly what happened.
My hero.
What's it like...
life as a spy I mean?
Classified.
Oh, right. I forgot.
But you said
"secret agent"
and nobody says
secret agent
and you do that a lot.
You get things
not quite right...
like you don't
belong here.
Rain, you're fantasizing.
And you're insulting
my intelligence.
Yesterday afternoon,
I picked up a UFO in orbit.
Today, my life
is completely out of control,
so don't think
I'm too stupid to notice.
I apologize.
Accepted.
Would you also accept that there
are lives at stake here?
The more you keep
asking me questions,
the more difficult
you make things for everybody.
I'll try.
So...
why'd you become an astronomer?
My brother.
Had a telescope,
a little refractor.
You could barely see
in the tree house next door
actually, but...
it was enough.
It was enough to see
the rings of Saturn.
I remember...
I remember I used
to think that they looked like
jewels
from pirate's treasure.
All I ever wanted since then
was to...
reach up and touch them.
TUVOK:
Good morning.
Agent Tuvok,
what's up?
Breakfast is up.
Have you made
any progress?
I think so.
Chili burritos,
footlong hot dogs,
and Goliath Gulps.
This is not
a breakfast.
This is an afternoon
at Dodger Stadium.
And that is
a non sequitur.
Would you please hand me
a burrito?
Everything you guys do
is just a little bit off.
These things
are kind of crude.
So much for sending
a locator signal.
There is another option.
The radio dish
at the observatory.
We could use the same setup.
ROBINSON:
The same setup
that I used to send that message
to your...
whatever it is up in orbit.
We will require your assistance.
No kidding.
Well?
Not on an empty stomach.
CHAKOTAY:
Starling downloaded
nearly 20 percent
of our computer core
while we were trying to beam
the timeship
out of his building.
TORRES:
I'm replacing those programs
as quickly as I can,
but some of it
isn't retrievable.
Like the doctor.
There's literally nothing
left of him. He's just gone.
Unfortunately, the doctor
is only one of our problems.
Our weapons are off-line.
Tuvok and Paris are missing
somewhere in Los Angeles,
and we've confirmed
Captain Braxton's hypothesis.
If Starling does attempt
a flight to the future,
it will most likely
end in disaster.
Captain, I've analyzed
Braxton's schematic.
The temporal technology
is incredibly complex.
TORRES:
No matter how much a genius
this Starling might be,
he is not a trained pilot
from the 29th century.
Without the exact calibration,
that ship will rip
the time-space continuum apart.
The instant he jumps
to the 29th century,
there won't be
a 29th century--
not for Earth, anyway.
The entire solar system
will be destroyed.
I want that timeship.
Long-range transporters are
still down.
We'd have to drop
out of orbit again.
Captain, I strongly
recommend against that.
The more legitimate
news organizations
have apparently decided that
the Voyager image is fraudulent.
However, I've also
been monitoring
more official channels
and the United States Military
is taking things just
a little more seriously.
If we risk another pass
through the lower atmosphere
there's a chance of getting
intercepted by the air force.
If we can't get
to the ship...
maybe we can get to the man.
Torres, I want you to--
WOMAN:
Captain Janeway,
I'm receiving a transmission
from Lieutenant Tuvok,
audio only.
Mr. Tuvok, report.
TUVOK:
Lieutenant Paris and I are
at the Griffith Observatory
in the Hollywood Hills.
We have modified
the satellite dish transmitter
to carry and receive
Voyager communication
frequencies.
I regret
the bad connection.
It's quite all right, Mr. Tuvok.
What's happened?
We have become associated
with a young woman
employed at the astronomical
laboratory.
It was she who sent
the message to Voyager
but her lab is
under the supervision
of an individual named
Henry Starling.
Oh, we've met Mr. Starling.
He has the timeship,
and he's the one
who will cause the disaster
in the 29th century.
Then it would seem,
we must find a way to stop him.
Tell me about this young woman.
Can we trust her?
She and Lieutenant Paris
appear to be bonding
on a cross-cultural level.
I would have to say yes.
Ask if she'd be willing
to help us.
How's it going?
I find your interest
in my well-being
to be less than genuine.
Try to be
a little more grateful, doc.
The schematics I downloaded
from your ship
indicated you were stuck
in the sick bay
24 hours a day.
I recently suffered
a severe program loss
and I'm still
in the process
of retrieving
my memory files
but apparently,
on a few occasions
I have been projected
into other locations.
Undoubtedly you are using
a similar procedure.
My holographic simulator.
We use it to test
our new microchip designs.
I projected you through
the emitters in the office.
Your program
really isn't very sophisticated.
That is a matter of opinion.
Now, would you please return me
to my vessel?
Can't do that. Not yet.
I've a few questions
I want answered.
If you have need
of medical expertise
I would refer you
to a more local physician.
All Captain Janeway's talk
about a disaster
I caused is just smoke.
You came here
to steal my timeship.
That is simply not the case.
That timeship is
from the 29th century--
technology 500 years
more advanced
than anything you've got.
You'd love to get
your hands on it.
You figured I'd
be an easy target--
some backwards 20th century
Neanderthal who doesn't know
what he's got, but you found
out otherwise, didn't you?
A paranoid response indicative
of bipolar personality disorder.
If my history is accurate
Southern California
in the late 20th century
had no shortage
of psychotherapists--
competent and otherwise.
I suggest you find one.
Now...
return me to Voyager.
I've learned
your weapons are damaged,
your ship's teleporter
is half-shot,
but I didn't get
all the personnel files.
I have to know my enemy.
Give me Captain Janeway's
psychological profile.
I'm a doctor, not a data base.
I'd say you're a little bit
of both. Start talking.
Or suffer the consequences?
Hardly.
I'm a hologram.
I experience neither pain...
nor fear of death.
You have no means
of coercing me.
( gasps )
Pain.
It's an interesting sensation,
isn't it?
I...
I never realized...
how unpleasant it could be?
( tapping keys )
( gasps )
This is what burning feels like.
For a human to experience
what you're going through
right now
he'd have to be on fire.
( tapping keys )
( groans )
( panting )
How?
By reconfiguring
your tactile response sensors.
Easy as proverbial pie.
Feeling more cooperative?
( intercom beeps )
I'm in a meeting, Dave.
Put her through.
Mr. Starling...
oh, my god, I'm so scared.
They're going to find me.
I don't know what to do.
Take it easy, Rain.
Everything's okay.
Everything's not okay. People
are shooting at me.
They're going to find me.
I don't know what to do.
Yes, you do.
You're going to jump in a cab
and come to my office.
You'll be safe here.
No, they'll find me.
Where are you?
Metro Plaza...
by the fountain.
Please come get me.
Please.
I'll send somebody.
No!
You.
I'm really scared.
I'll be right there.
He bought it...
sort of.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
His voice sounded
a little suspicious.
Pack a lunch, Doc.
We're going for a walk.
In case you
have forgotten
I can only appear
in a room equipped
with a holographic
projection system.
In short,
I'm going nowhere.
Interferometric dispersion
is on-line.
That should take care
of any radar detection.
And I've configured
the shields
to disguise
our visual profile.
Unless somebody gets
right on top of us
we should look like
a small 20th century aircraft.
The transporters
are on-line.
We should be within range
in about ten minutes.
You can see the entire
baja peninsula.
I'd forgotten how
beautiful the view is
from this altitude.
I never thought
I'd see it again.
You trained as a pilot
in North America, didn't you?
That's right.
My first year at the Academy.
Then I went to Venus
for a couple of months
to learn how to handle
atmospheric storms
and then I dodged asteroids
for a semester
in the belt.
It sounds like you had more fun
at the Academy than I did.
I remember dodging
a few punches in the lab.
Only you, B'elanna, could start
a brawl in astro-theory 101.
I guess I was just
a little more...
enthusiastic...
in those days.
I guess so.
Chakotay...
what if we're stuck here?
What if we can't
find a way back?
There are still
a few isolated places
left in this century.
We'd have to keep low profiles.
We'd have to get jobs.
I've thought about pursuing
archaeology full-time.
Maybe I could teach at
a university or work on
one of the important digs
in Central America.
There was still a lot of
important discoveries to be made
in this century.
I could win a Nobel Prize.
So much for a low profile.
What about you?
"Highly qualified Klingon
seeks position as engineer."
I'd hire you in a second.
Let's start our descent.
Approach course laid in.
Full power to thrusters.
Watch out for birds.
( beeping )
Paris to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
Starling's arrived,
with the doctor.
What? How is that possible?
I don't know.
Are you within range?
Almost.
Another two minutes.
I don't know, Doc...
you were awfully quiet
in the ride over here.
I'm not programmed
to make small talk.
Maybe just a
little bit anxious
about being out
in the real world.
It's just another
environment to me.
Mind your manners, Doc.
If your shipmates
start any trouble
you'll be holo-dust.
I've triangulated the position
of the van, Chakotay.
Stand by for
tricorder uplink.
You'll be able to lock on
the moment starling is inside.
Mr. Starling,
I'm so glad you're here.
Tell your new
friends to come out
or their colleague
here is going to die.
What are you
talking about?
Let's go.
Oh, my van is this way.
We're taking my car.
Well... I left my stuff
in the van.
I'll send somebody
back for it.
Is there a problem?
No.
He's heading in
the wrong direction.
They're not going
to the van.
Mr. Chakotay,
there is a problem.
( beeping )
That... that's the guy
that tried to kill me.
No, he was trying
to rescue you.
Where are we going?
To my office.
You'll be safe there.
Office, right.
We're recalibrating
Starling's position.
You're going to have
to take him out of his own car.
There may not be
enough time.
I've determined
the coordinates.
Now, Chakotay!
We've got a lock
on Starling's position.
Energizing.
Dunbar, take
the surface streets.
The 101's a nightmare
this time of...
oh, my god!
Run!
( beeping )
Pattern buffer's overloading.
He's activated some device.
It's interfering
with the transport.
( grunting )
( groaning )
Hmm!
( moaning )
( engine starts )
Oh!
Are you all right?
I guess so.
Doctor?
I've been equipped
with an autonomous,
self-sustaining
mobile holo-emitter.
In short, I am footloose
and fancy-free.
Chakotay:
Captain we've got Starling
in our transporter buffers
but we can't rematerialize him.
The interference is disrupting
computer pathways.
Aft thrusters are down.
Captain, we're close enough
to use the short-range
transporter.
Janeway to transporter room one.
Lock directly
on to the shuttle's
pattern buffers and energize.
WOMAN:
Acknowledged.
Chakotay, we're taking over
from here.
Mr. Kim, let's go.
The buffers are purged.
They've taken Starling
off our hands.
We're losing altitude.
He's got what looks like
a tricorder.
It's putting out some kind of
interference signal.
KIM:
I'm isolating it
and suppressing the amplitude.
Got him.
Damn it.
Janeway to sick bay.
Medical emergency
in transporter room one.
KES:
Acknowledged, Captain.
Propulsion is off-line.
Voyager, we're going down.
( door opens )
Where are we?
This one looks
like an Indian...
and that one...
I don't know what
her story is.
What's that thing on her head?
( growling )
( laughing )
Careful, butch.
She looks like a fighter.
Who are you?
You first.
Are you spying
on us... chief?
( chuckles )
No.
Just passing by.
In your new
stealth plane?
Who sent you?
Nobody sent us.
We had engine trouble.
I don't believe her. They're
wearing military uniforms,
flying a secret plane.
They're coming for us.
"U.S.S." equals
federal government.
The federal government
is the beast.
We are not from the beast.
Just take us to our plane.
Shut up!
( Groans )
That'll be all!
Call for reinforcements.
It's going to be a long day.
ROBINSON:
I've gone out with guys
who've disappeared
into thin air
on the first date.
I assume she is speaking
figuratively.
But I have never
actually seen it happen.
And you , Mr. Leisure suit!
There's a name
I hadn't considered.
That guy punched
you a bunch of times.
You should have a black eye
or a swollen lip a broken nose.
Try to relax.
You appear to be...
hallucinating.
Oh, is that what I am?
I'm hallucinating.
Rain, I'm sorry you got
dragged into all this.
( phone ringing )
Tuvok here.
Tuvok, we've got Starling
but we've lost contact
with Chakotay and Torres.
Their shuttle went down
over Arizona.
Mr. Kim is transmitting
the coordinates
to your tricorder.
I want you to find them.
Aye, captain.
Tuvok out.
Mr. Starling
is under control.
I suggest you return
to Chronowerx
and continue
the business there.
The doctor and I must
make our way to Arizona.
He suffered minor
synaptic stress
during the extended transport
enough to cause
unconsciousness
but not any permanent damage.
Can you bring him
out of it?
Yes, Captain.
Welcome
to the 24th century.
I took the precaution
of removing your tricorder.
That's what it's called,
by the way.
It didn't work.
It should have blocked
your ship's teleporter.
It works perfectly.
You just don't know
how to use it.
Give me some credit, captain.
I did pretty well
for a primitive.
Well, that's all over now.
I've won
so disable the force field
around Chronowerx.
I want that timeship.
You're in no position to be
making any demands, Captain.
On the contrary.
What are you going to do--
shoot me?
The thought has crossed my mind.
Well, it wouldn't
get you anything.
I've rigged the timeship.
If you try to
teleport it again
if you even go near it
Los Angeles will look like
the face of the moon.
You'd destroy
an entire city?
You don't care
about the future,
you don't care
about the present.
Does anything
matter to you, Mr. Starling?
The betterment of mankind.
It doesn't look like that.
Why do you think I want
to go to the future?
A vacation?
To get more technology.
That's why you're launching
the timeship.
I've cannibalized the ship
itself as much as I can.
There's nothing left to base
a commercial product on.
And the future is just waiting
to be exploited.
You just don't get it, do you?
I created the micro-computer
revolution.
Using technology
you never should have had.
Irrelevant. My products
benefit the entire world.
Without me, there would be
no laptops, no internet,
no bar-code readers.
What's good for Chronowerx
is good for everybody.
I can't stop now. One trip
to the 29th century,
and I can bring back
enough technology
to start the next
ten computer revolutions.
If you even attempt
to travel to the future,
you risk creating
a temporal explosion
that could cost
billions of lives,
including your own.
I'm willing to take that risk.
In my time... Mr. Starling,
no human being would dream
of endangering the future
to gain advantage
in the present.
Captain, the future
you're talking about--
that's 900 years from now.
I can't be concerned
about that right now.
I have a company to run
and a whole world full
of people waiting for me
to make their lives
a little bit better.
Computer,
reactivate force field.
Chronowerx stock
is about to crash.
There are two forces
at work in the world--
the drive
toward collectivity
and the drive
toward individuality.
You are the former
and I am the latter.
We told you
we are not from
the United States government
and we are not...
The beast has many heads
and I'm looking at two of them.
Listen, I used to think
violence could be
the solution to a problem
but it's not true.
You are no patriot.
I was a freedom fighter...
so I thought.
That gun will
get you nowhere.
Porter!
They're coming--
the Feds.
How many?
Three cars and a chopper
two miles up Edgemont road.
This is it, men.
Get into position
behind the house.
Butchie and me
will take these two.
Looks like
your friends out there
still believe in violence.
Too bad for you.
ROBINSON:
Let's recap.
U.F.O. in orbit,
laser pistols,
people vanishing.
I've seen every episode
of Mission: Impossible.
You're not secret agents.
I told you,
I can't talk about it.
Well, you can't keep
a girl from hypothesizing.
I'm a scientist.
I'm thinking...
I'm thinking
alternate dimension.
I'm thinking...
Close Encounter.
Whatever.
Talk about a motley crew--
we have the doctor,
a guy with the worst,
worst taste in clothing
I've ever seen.
Tuvok-- what a freakasaurus.
Has the guy ever
cracked a smile?
Not that I can recall.
And you-- Tom Paris.
Hmm, sexy...
in a howdy doody
sort of way.
Pretty goofy,
although sometimes
I think you're the smartest man
I've ever met.
All this running around you do--
your mission--
you're so dedicated, you know?
Like you care about something
more than just your own...
little life.
Is that so unusual?
Yeah.
Whoa.
I missed the turn.
COMPUTER:
Sat-com 47-- activating.
Engage Starling location sweep.
Sweep underway.
TUVOK:
We're in Arizona.
Chakotay and Torres
are 30 kilometers
northeast of Phoenix.
Good. Get to them
as soon as you can.
KIM:
Captain, there's
a transport in progress.
What?
Starling's gone.
He's beamed to the surface.
He's got some kind
of satellite in orbit.
It sent a
transporter signal
through our shields
like they weren't there.
Where's Starling now?
Tracking the signal.
He's back at the
Chronowerx building.
Mr. Dunbar, good work.
I think it's time
to get out of here.
I guess this is good-bye.
Guess it is.
Listen... are you
busy tomorrow night?
'Cause, um...
you know,
we should hang together.
I can't.
Oh. Well,
what about this weekend?
Um...
You're married.
Absolutely not.
Just... very busy.
Oh... yeah, you got to
get back to Mars, right?
Hmm... Saturn.
That's perfect.
I told you
I always loved Saturn.
So, give me your phone number.
Rain...
( tricorder beeping )
Tachyon emissions.
They're moving the timeship.
Timeship?
What are you talking about?
You wouldn't mind hanging
with me for a while longer, huh?
MAN:
We want the aircraft
and the occupants
from the aircraft.
Get off my land!
What are they going
to do when they find
a half-Klingon in here?
MAN:
Who the hell
are you two?!
TUVOK:
Please stand aside, officer.
MAN:
I'm warning both of you!
( phasers blasting )
They've got lasers!
A black man
and some bald guy.
( phaser fire and gunfire
outside )
( phaser fire only )
( approaching footsteps )
God in heaven help us.
Divine intervention is...
unlikely.
( groans )
( sighs )
Tuvok's at the shuttle.
He's starting repairs.
Doctor, how..?
It's a long story,
commander.
Suffice it to say
I'm making a house call.
It's Paris again. On audio.
Status report, Tom.
We just turned off
the main highway
onto a desert road.
Hi. This is
Rain Robinson.
You don't know me,
but the point is
there is zero traffic
on this road.
They're going to know
we're following them.
Thank you, Ms. Robinson.
I'll keep that in mind.
Tom, we've scanned the area.
There appears to be
a small landing field,
about ten kilometers
ahead of you.
It could be
his launch site.
Stay on him.
Our weapons are still off-line
and Torres hasn't finished
repairing the shuttle.
It might all be up to you.
I'll do my best.
Paris out.
Look out!
( tires squealing )
Get in behind him.
What?
Right off his bumper.
A little closer.
Forget it.
One more meter!
Just shoot!
( engine sputtering )
It's flooded.
Give it a second.
Well, do you
think we got him?
I think so.
( sighs )
( rumbling )
Come on.
( van engine sputtering )
Jump!
Chakotay to Paris.
What's your status?
We're fine.
Good shooting.
Wasn't there supposed to be
a timeship in that truck?
I'm scanning the debris.
It was a temporal
transponder
set to give off
tachyon signals.
Chakotay to Voyager.
The timeship's
not here, Captain.
It was a ruse.
Starling's going to launch
from a different site.
Activate hyper-impulse.
COMPUTER:
Hyper-impulse drive engaged.
Let's do it.
Command confirmed.
The timeship is entering
the upper ionosphere.
Track his course.
Janeway to shuttlecraft,
return to Voyager immediately.
CHAKOTAY:
Acknowledged, Captain.
Phasers are still off-line.
I've armed the photon torpedoes,
but we still can't fire them.
The launch activation sequencers
aren't responding.
I think I can reroute
fire command through the helm.
There's no time.
Take the bridge, Mr. Kim.
Should be second nature
to you by now.
Captain...
Open the access portal
to torpedo bay one.
I'm going in there to
reconfigure for manual launch.
Captain, with
the activation sequencers down,
you'd have to launch
from inside the tube.
It's too dangerous.
The plasma exhaust--
You have your orders.
I've got the transporters
back on-line.
Mr. Paris, stand by.
We're bringing you aboard.
Acknowledged.
Your spaceship's waiting.
I've never met anyone
quite like you...
and I don't think
I ever will.
Same here.
Say hi to Saturn for me.
I will.
Initiate temporal inversion.
Initiating.
KIM:
Bridge to Janeway.
The shuttle is back on board.
Good. I'm nearly there.
Captain, the timeship
has jumped to warp one.
Go to warp.
We can't lose him now.
Welcome to the bridge,
Doctor.
Thank you.
It's a pleasure to be here.
CHAKOTAY:
Status?
The captain's in
torpedo tube one.
She's preparing
for a manual launch.
CHAKOTAY:
Doctor, get
down there.
How exactly do I get
to torpedo tube one?
Ensign Kaplan,
go with him.
KAPLAN:
Aye, sir.
The timeship is powering
its temporal field generator.
Starling will be able to open
a rift within seconds.
KIM:
Commander, the field
he's creating-- it's unstable.
TORRES:
If he enters
the rift like this
that timeship will create
a temporal explosion.
Events are occurring just
as Captain Braxton predicted.
The disaster may well
be inevitable.
Fate, Tuvok?
I won't accept that.
Close to within ten kilometers.
We'll ram him if we have to.
Aye, sir.
Temporal core has reached
cascade potential.
Penetration point
at 96-mark-047.
Janeway to bridge.
I've reconfigured
for manual launch.
Arm the torpedo.
Torpedo armed.
Lock on target.
Locked on.
Hail starling.
KIM:
On screen.
CHAKOTAY:
This is Voyager.
Pull away from the rift.
Or what?
Your weapons are down, friend.
See you... sometime.
Chakotay to Janeway.
Captain,
we have no other choice.
KIM:
He's entering
the rift.
Fire!
( groans )
( alarm beeping )
Uh-oh.
Captain, I insist you
come to sick bay.
There'll be plenty of
time for that, Doctor.
The bridge is
yours, Captain.
Is there a chance in hell
we can reopen that rift?
Captain, the rift is opening.
KIM:
There's something
coming out.
It's the timeship.
Let's see it.
TUVOK:
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Captain Braxton?
Do you know me?
Yes, unfortunately.
You tried to destroy our ship
in the 24th century
and the next time we saw you
you were an old man,
homeless in 1996.
I never experienced
that time-line.
Then what are you doing here?
In my century,
we can scan time--
much as you use sensors
to scan space.
The temporal integrity
commission detected your vessel
over 20th century Earth.
I was sent
to correct that anomaly.
Prepare to follow me back
into the rift.
I'm returning you
to your own time
to your previous coordinates
in the delta quadrant.
Captain...
we've been trying
to get home to Earth
for the last two years.
Can you return us
to our century,
but keep us here
in the Alpha quadrant?
I'm sorry.
Temporal prime directive.
I'm afraid you're on your own.
Braxton out.
The timeship
is re-entering the rift.
Mr. Paris...
follow him in.
Aye, captain.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
stardate 50312.5.
We are again
in the Delta quadrant
at the exact time and place
we first encountered
the timeship.
I've resumed a course
for Earth,
and I've ordered the crew
to the mess hall for a toast.
( laughter )
ALL:
Cheers.
Hear, hear.
To the future.
How long will you be
out and about, doctor?
If you're referring
to my newfound mobility
that is entirely
up to me.
I'm still trying to
figure out exactly
how the doctor's
autonomous emitter works,
but it looks like
downloading him
back into the ship's computer
isn't going to be much
of a problem.
Apparently the reverse
is also true.
I will be able to make use
of the emitter as casually
as you might
slip on a pair of shoes.
It's a little more
involved than that.
You know, Kes,
now that I'll be to-and-fro,
your responsibilities
in sick bay will increase.
I'm up to the challenge,
doctor, but what about you?
There's going to be more to
your life now than sick bay.
Nothing I can't handle.
You know, captain, I've always
wanted a little more privacy.
Perhaps under the circumstances,
my own quarters.
One step at a time, doctor.
You should have seen it
when the parking
enforcement officer
came over to the van.
Tuvok tried to use
pure Vulcan logic
to talk her out of
giving us a citation.
Did it work?
Of course not.
Given Mr. Paris'
alleged familiarity
with 20th-century America,
it is a wonder we survived
the experience at all.
Tuvok...
has anyone ever told you
you're a real freakasaurus?