( majestic theme playing )
( sighs )
( all clapping )
Incredible.
Absolutely thrilling.
All I can say
is...wow! Ha.
What about you,
Mr. Vulcan?
Isn't that just...?
Wow! Ha.
Your inarticulate
expression of awe
notwithstanding,
Mr. Neelix,
it was
a fascinating spectacle.
That's the edge
of the shock wave.
The pressure's
over 90 kilopascals.
Thirty percent more
than we predicted.
Tom, back us off
at full impulse.
I want to stay ahead
of the brunt of that wave.
Yes, ma'am.
Congratulations, everyone.
Only two other crews
in the history of Starfleet
have witnessed
a supernova explosion.
But neither one was this close,
less than ten billion
kilometers.
Definitely a record.
Who brought the champagne?
Champagne? Captain, if I thought
you wanted champagne, I...
JANEWAY:
Relax, Neelix.
It's a figure of speech.
Thanks for inviting us
to watch with you, captain.
It's really
gotten me interested
in learning more about
stellar phenomena.
Just remember, Kes,
anyone can stargaze
on the bridge--
even a hologram
with a mobile emitter
but the real action
will always be in sick bay.
How'd those shield modifications
hold up, B'elanna?
Less than
a seven percent power drain.
Good job. Chakotay,
what do you say
we get started analyzing those
carbon conversion readings?
Captain, you've been on
the bridge for fourteen hours.
Don't you think you
deserve a little rest?
Harry and I will get to work
on the astrometric analysis
and we'll give you
a full report in the morning.
You win.
I'll see you at 0700.
Janeway to security.
Intruder alert.
There's no need to call
room service, Kathy.
I've already ordered.
Oh, Q.
You did say
you wanted champagne.
Janeway to security.
Intruder alert.
Oh, it's no use.
I've taken the proverbial
phone off the hook.
After all, we don't want
any interruptions.
What are you doing here?
To us.
There is no us, Q.
The night is young, and
the sheets... are satin.
I want you out, but first,
get rid of this bed.
I have no intention
of getting between
those Starfleet
issue sheets.
They give me a
terrible rash.
Well, since you won't
be getting in the bed
I wouldn't worry about it.
Oh, Kathy...
don't be such a prude.
Admit it.
It has been a while.
And it's going to
be a while longer.
Now get out.
So tense.
Why don't you slip into
something more comfortable?
If you think this puerile
attempt at seduction
is going to work, you're
even more self-deluded
than I thought.
Oh, I see.
You think I'm interested
in some tawdry
one-night stand.
That's because I haven't
told you why I'm here yet.
Out of all the females,
of all the species
in all the galaxies,
I have chosen you
to be the mother
of my child.
I know that you're
probably asking yourself
"Why would a brilliant,
handsome,
"dashingly omnipotent being
like Q want to mate
with a scrawny little
bipedal specimen like me?"
Let me guess.
No one else in the universe
will have you.
Nonsense.
I could have chosen
a Klingon Targ
the Romulan empress,
a Cyrillian microbe.
Really? I beat out
a single-celled organism?
How flattering.
It's an overwhelming
honor, isn't it?
I can't get you
out of my mind.
You're confident,
passionate, beautiful.
And totally uninterested.
Kathy, you can't leave.
My cosmic clock is ticking.
Besides, you have no idea
what you're missing.
Foreplay with a Q
can last for decades.
Sorry, but I'm busy
for the next 60 or 70 years.
Oh, I see. This is one
of those silly human rituals.
You're playing hard to get.
As far as you're concerned,
Q, I'm impossible to get.
Goody. A challenge.
This is going to be fun.
( sighing )
Janeway to bridge.
Chakotay here, Captain.
I thought you were going
to get some sleep.
I've just had a visit from Q.
He's gone now,
but I want
to be notified immediately
if he reappears
anywhere on the ship
or if anything odd
starts to happen.
Acknowledged.
What did he want?
Let's just say he had
a personal request.
Captain?
I'm not sure what
he's really up to,
but I have
a feeling he'll be back.
Janeway out.
( sighing )
( door beeping )
Come in.
I've got those carbon conversion
readings from the supernova.
Thank you.
Is there something else?
Have you heard
anything more from Q?
No. I wish I could believe
he's gone for good.
I was wondering
just what you meant
when you said he made
a personal request.
He wants to mate with me.
( exhaling )
I see.
Obviously, it's
out of the question
and I suspect it's
a smoke screen.
Knowing Q he's probably
got some hidden agenda.
Maybe...
Chakotay...
I know I don't have
any right to feel this way,
but this bothers
the hell out of me.
Q:
I do believe
you're jealous.
Why didn't you tell me
there was another man?
Because there isn't.
I'm just not
interested in you.
Any more questions?
I was wondering, Kathy,
what could anyone
possibly see
in this big oaf anyway?
Is it the tattoo?
Because mine's bigger.
Not big enough.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
stardate 50384.2.
Q's unannounced visits
continue.
Since I suspect
he's up to something
more than pursuing me,
I've instructed the crew
to take every opportunity
to uncover his true motives.
Who says
crew performance reports
have to be a chore?
( both moaning )
It sure beats
working on the bridge.
Now, if we
could just convince
the captain to start holding
morning briefings in here...
that'll be the day.
Nice program, Tommy,
but it's all
just so much hollow
pleasure, isn't it?
All right, Q, we'll bite.
What do you want?
Guys... I just don't
understand your captain.
I've tried everything--
filling the bridge with roses
writing Drabian love sonnets,
serenading her in her bath.
Oh, I'll bet she loved that one.
But no matter what
lengths I go to win her heart
she rejects me. Me!
How, I ask you,
is that possible?
Did it ever occur to you that
she just doesn't like you?
No.
Look, Q, we've been told
about your appearances
on the Enterprise.
We know your little visits
usually turn out
to be more than meet the eye
so save
your broken-heart routine
and tell us
what you're really after.
I just thought
that the two of you
might be able to give me
some advice
on how to break through
Kathy's icy exterior.
You know, man-to-man.
My advice would
be to give up
before you embarrass yourself
any more than you already have.
Come on, Harry.
We're not going to get
a straight answer
out of this guy.
( slurping )
You-- bar rodent-- another one
of these... fruity concoctions.
Not unless you tell me
why you're bothering
Captain Janeway.
Captain Janeway?
Now, that's a subject
I want to discuss.
Tell me, what are some
of her favorite things?
Chocolate truffles,
stuffed animals,
erotic art?
You can't bribe
Captain Janeway.
Oh, no?
Isn't that what you do?
What are you
talking about?
I understand that you
acquire things for her--
create little
interesting diversions
prepare little tasty treats.
After all, why else
would she be fond of your...
fur-lined face?
Do you want to know
what Captain Janeway
likes about me?
I'll tell you.
I am respectful, loyal,
and most of all, sincere,
and those are qualities
which someone like you
could never hope
to possess.
( chuckles )
( faint whimpering )
( gasps )
This isn't going to work, Q.
How can you ignore that face?
He's adorable,
but this has to stop.
Please. Accept him...
as a small token
of my affection.
No.
Suit yourself.
May we talk?
Just talk?
( clearing throat )
I'm... afraid that I
haven't been sincere.
When you first asked
why I wanted to have
a child with you
I made jokes,
bragged about my prowess,
engaged in sexual innuendo.
I was using all that
to cover up my true feelings.
And I suppose
you want to share
your true feelings
with me now.
I'm lonely.
Lonely?
Oh, I know it's hard to believe
but I've been single
for billions of years.
It was fun at first--
gallivanting around the galaxy
using my omnipotence to impress
females of every species.
( laughs )
The fact of the matter
is that it left me empty.
I want someone
to love me for myself.
I guess what I'm saying is...
I want a relationship.
I just thought
if you and I had a child
it would give me that kind
of stability and security
that I've been missing.
Sorry, Q.
I'm not buying it.
Oh.
All right.
Let's see if you buy this.
You're stuck out here, thousands
of light years from home
and you aren't getting
any younger, are you?
All your hopes for
home, hearth or family
grow dimmer
every day.
Admit it, Kathryn.
You're lonely too.
And you wonder if you will
ever... have a child.
You're right.
I would like to have
a child someday...
Oh.
But not with you.
Why not?
I'm just not the right
kind of woman for you, Q.
Truer words
were never spoken.
Q! How did
you find me?
Never mind that.
What are you doing
with that dog?
I'm not talking about the puppy.
Can't you see
I'm busy here?
Stop stalking me!
You should be back
in the Continuum.
Excuse me...
but who are you exactly?
Kathryn Janeway,
may I present... Q.
Not just any Q--
his Q.
We were involved
for a while.
About four billion years.
And now you desert me
to pollute the Continuum
with the DNA of this...
narrow little being.
I never said
it was exclusive.
Stay away from him.
Look...
Miss Q, I'll save you
a lot of trouble.
I have zero interest in him.
Oh, now you see
what you've done?
And I was finally
making progress.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Janeway.
You'd better come in here.
On my way.
I'd really appreciate
it if you would take this
domestic squabble off my ship.
Report.
CHAKOTAY:
You're not going
to believe this, captain.
But another star in this
cluster just went supernova.
It's .02 light years
from our current position.
KIM:
Make that
two supernovas, commander.
I just picked up another
one at 217 mark 47.
Estimated time
of implosion: 67 seconds.
Get us out of here, Tom.
I can't. The subspace
shock wave from the star
is collapsing
the warp field.
Red alert.
Tuvok, increase power
to the shields.
Tom, lay in a course away
from that shock wave.
Maximum impulse.
A star going supernova is
an event that occurs
once every century
in this galaxy.
Now we're about
to witness our third
in less than three days--
all in the same sector.
Why do I suspect you have
something to do with this?
She may be a member
of an intellectually
challenged species,
but she's right.
Your irresponsible behavior
is continuing
to have cosmic consequences.
Will you stop overreacting?!
Always nagging.
Now you see why I left her.
Are you causing
these supernovas?
Well, not exactly.
What's that
supposed to mean?
PARIS:
It's no use, captain.
The shock wave
is too fast for us.
Try evasive maneuvers.
I'm afraid a course correction
will be futile, captain.
There are three distinct
shock waves
heading toward us
on various trajectories.
It will be impossible
to avoid them all.
Divert auxiliary power
to the shields.
You have the ability to get us
out of here, so do it.
CHAKOTAY:
16 seconds to impact. I'm not
sure if the shields will hold.
Do something, Q!
Well..
if you insist.
( snaps fingers )
That two-timing toad!
Contact with the first
shock wave
within three seconds,
commander.
All hands,
brace for impact.
Q?
Where have you taken me?
Well, I must admit
your gown is very becoming.
I don't have time
for your little fantasies.
Return me to Voyager.
This is no fantasy.
You're in the Q Continuum now.
The Continuum?
That's right.
I'm simply allowing you
to perceive it in a context
your human mind can comprehend.
The last time
you brought me here
it looked like some sort of
way station on a desert road.
Ha. It was awfully
drab, wasn't it?
But this -- this is
a much more colorful
representation for a human
of American descent,
don't you think?
An elegant manor house,
a beautiful southern belle,
a dashing union officer
determined to win
her affections
despite her hatred
for Yankee interlopers...
Enough. The only thing that
interests me right now
is the welfare of
my ship and crew.
Well, I'm sure your first
officer-- "Chuckles," is it?
I'm sure he's
got everything
under control
for the moment.
I'd like to make sure
of that myself
if you don't mind.
This has gone
way beyond your ship.
It's even gone
beyond you and me.
This is about the future
of the Continuum itself.
Stop speaking in riddles
and tell me what's going on.
I'll do better
than that.
I'll show you.
The Continuum
is burning.
The Q are in the middle
of a civil war.
JANEWAY:
Start explaining.
Do you remember
our friend Quinn?
Q who committed suicide
aboard Voyager?
Do you recall what
I said might happen
if he were allowed
to take his own life?
You said it would represent
an interruption
to the Continuum...
that it could have
dire consequences.
I'd say a civil war
is pretty dire, wouldn't you?
His death caused this conflict.
It caused chaos and upheaval...
because even though he was gone
his calls for freedom
and individualism
continued to echo
in the ears of those
who believed
in his teachings--
myself among them.
I sounded the trumpet
and carried the banner.
Naturally, others followed.
The forces of the status quo
tried to crush us
once and for all
but we fought back
and now there's a cosmic
struggle for supremacy
and the battle is spreading
causing hazardous repercussions
throughout the galaxy.
Oh, the supernovas.
You might call them...
"Galactic cross fire."
It's terrible, isn't it?
But it's also
a wonderful opportunity.
I fail to see anything
wonderful about a war.
War can be an engine of change.
War can transform
a society for the better.
Your own civil war
brought about an end
to slavery and oppression.
But our civil war came at a time
before mankind had learned
to resolve disputes
without bloodshed.
Surely, the Q have
evolved to a point
where you can find
a non-violent way
to resolve a conflict.
That's where you come in.
What do I have to do
with any of this, Q?
I want you to help me
transform the Continuum
in the same way your civil war
transformed the nation.
By mating with you?!
I know.
It's brilliant, isn't it?
I don't see how a baby
is going to end a war
being fought by a race
of omnipotent beings.
It's simple.
Mating will create
a new breed of Q, which will
combine my omnipotence
and infinite intellect
with the best that humanity
has to offer.
You believe human DNA
is going to restore peace?
Precisely.
What the Continuum needs
right now
is an infusion of fresh blood.
A new sensibility.
A new leader.
A new messiah.
( shouts and gunfire )
Think of it, Kathy--
our child will be
like a precious stone
tossed into the cosmic lake
sending endless ripples
of human conscience
and compassion
to wash up on every distant
shore of the universe.
What greater contribution
could a being of
your limited power
ever hope to make?
What is more important
to humanity than peace?
I'm offering you
the opportunity
to be the mother of peace.
( gunfire )
Well, what's it
going to be?
( gunshots,
cries out )
Q!
( groaning )
You're bleeding.
( gunshots )
( explosion )
Report.
Shield strength
is at 20%.
Hull damage on decks
nine through 14.
Minor injuries
reported on all decks.
Warp drive is off-line.
KIM:
Commander, according to
these readings
the shock waves have
knocked us 16 billion
kilometers from our
previous location.
I want to know
what's going on here.
Where's Captain Janeway?
Let me go before I hurl
this ship and everyone on it
into the Therinian ice age.
I don't think you can.
Don't be ridiculous.
( snaps fingers )
I don't know how or why
but something's
affected your powers.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
still be here
and you wouldn't have a bruise
on your forehead.
Now start talking
before I hurl you
into the brig .
CHAKOTAY:
And it's the war
in the Continuum
that's causing
the supernovas?
May we presume that this
conflict is also responsible
for the weakening of your powers
and your inability
to return to the Continuum?
The Vulcan talent
for stating the obvious
never ceases to amaze me.
How were Q and
Captain Janeway
able to reenter
the Continuum
and you weren't?
I tried to return but
I was wounded in the process.
Don't try to understand it.
It's far beyond your limited
capacity to comprehend.
What's important is
I'm stuck here
with you mortals
while Q is probably
in the process
of irreparably
harming the Continuum
with that... woman.
Hmm! Tossed aside
for someone
five billion years younger.
If it weren't
so laughable, I'd cry.
Look, we want
our captain back,
and you obviously
want to get home.
Why don't we
help each other?
How could you
possibly help me?
There's got to be some way
to get back to the Continuum
besides snapping
your fingers.
Hmm. Well, there
is one possibility
but, somehow, I don't
think this rickety barge
or your half-witted crew members
are up to the challenge.
May I remind you, madam,
that this "rickety barge"
and its "half-witted crew"
Are your only hope
at the moment.
Ow! That hurts.
Be still. I never thought
a Q could be injured.
As I said, this is
only your perception
of what is happening.
I can assure you
those are not
mere cannon balls
and lead charges
being fired at us.
So they're some sort of...
Q weapons?
You'd be surprised
what innovative munitions
can be created
by one immortal being
who set his mind
on killing another.
MAN:
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
You're surrounded, Q.
Surrender now
and we'll be merciful.
Call a truce. Talk to them.
Maybe you can
resolve this peacefully.
MAN:
What's your answer, Q.
I'll never surrender,
you know that!
MAN:
Resume fire! Resume fire!
Q:
Get the rifle
in the corner.
Take the other window.
This is your fight, Q,
not mine!
If that's how you feel about it.
But if their weapons
can make me bleed
what do you think
they'll do to you?
( gunshots )
( explosion )
Oh!
Q?
Q, come on.
Oh!
Come on!
( explosion )
CHAKOTAY:
First officer's log,
stardate: 50392.7.
While we don't fully understand
the astrophysics
underlying her plan,
the female Q has suggested
several modifications
which may allow Voyager
to enter the Continuum.
Well?
Well, what?
Are you finished yet?
What you've asked us to do
requires a complete
reconfiguration
of the shield array.
It takes a while...
for us mere
mortals, that is.
Surely there's some way you
can speed up the process?
If you're in such a hurry why
don't you just snap your fingers
and do it yourself?
Oh, that's right.
You've lost your powers
and you need our help.
I don't think you understand.
It's imperative that I
get back to the Continuum
before Q mates
with your captain.
I understand perfectly.
You aren't the first female
who's ever had a man
run out on her.
I hope you're not comparing
some failed romance
in your pitiful existence to
my eternal association with Q?
You know, I have really had it
with this superiority complex
of yours.
It's not a complex, dear.
It's a fact.
Well, here's another fact:
if you don't stop pestering me
I'm never going to finish,
in which case,
your association with Q
might not be quite
as eternal as you think.
You know, I've always
liked Klingon females.
You've got such... spunk.
( gasps )
Where are we?
One of your faction's
encampments.
How?
I pulled you out of the mansion
and managed to hide you
from the enemy patrols.
Then I spotted
some of your people
retreating from the battle.
From the look of them, I'd say
you're not on the winning side.
You saved my life.
And now, it's time
to end all this.
I knew you'd come around.
I've been thinking
about what you said.
That creating a new Q
could bring an era of peace.
Oh, my wild, sweet Kathy.
I promise you won't regret it.
Oh, you're not going to have
a child with me.
You're going to mate with
that charming lady friend
of yours that appeared
on my ship.
Mate with another Q? Ridiculous.
Sounded to me like you and she
had a very long relationship.
Yes, but it was never physical.
I mean,
the Q are way beyond sex.
It's never been done.
Really?
Then how exactly did
the Q come into existence
in the first place?
The Q didn't come
into existence.
The Q have always existed.
Besides, I can only
mate with a species
capable of copulation...
like you.
But I don't love you, Q.
Yes, but what does that
have to do with it?
Everything.
It's the foundation of a family.
I could never have a child
with someone I didn't love,
much less give it up
to the Continuum.
Dearest Kathy, I would never
dream of having you give it up.
I mean, who would raise it?
Who would look after it?
I'm really not cut out
to be a wet nurse.
( sighing )
Oh... so you're not willing
to do the hard work?
I'm an idea man.
Hard work isn't my forte.
I'd change specialties
if I were you
'cause the kind of trouble
you're in
needs more than a quick fix.
You can't just sprinkle
a little human DNA
into the Continuum
and make everything all right.
Why not?
( sighs )
Those "best qualities
of humanity" you talked about
aren't a simple matter
of genetics.
Love, conscience,
compassion...
( groans )
They're attributes that mankind
has developed over centuries.
Values that have passed from
one generation to the next
taught by parents
to their children.
Creating a new kind
of Q is a noble idea,
but it will take more
than impregnating someone
and walking away.
If you want your offspring
to embrace your ideals
you're going to have
to teach them yourself.
Yes, but that's exactly
why I want you here--
to nourish and guide
the little tyke.
Think of the opportunities
here in the Continuum.
The entire universe would
be our child's playground.
Together, the two of you
could explore dimensions
you've never
even imagined.
Fess up.
Isn't it even...
slightly tempting?
I'd be lying if I said no.
What explorer
wouldn't be intrigued
by the idea of seeking out
whole new dimensions?
But I have
other responsibilities
and I won't just abandon them.
Ah, yes. The crew of
the intrepid starship Voyager.
Perhaps you'd be interested
in sending them home.
You've tempted me
with that prospect before
but frankly, your credibility
is more than a little suspect.
My crew and I will get home.
We're committed to that,
but we're going to do it
through hard work
and determination.
We are not looking
for a quick fix.
Even if I wanted to mate,
I wouldn't know how.
It's totally unprecedented.
You'll figure something out.
You are omnipotent,
after all.
I need time to think about it.
Time's up, Q.
You've got to stop this war
before it destroys
the Continuum.
Now, I'm taking
this white flag
and I'm going over
to the enemy camp
and I'm going to tell them
you're ready to talk
about terms for a cease-fire.
Kathy, don't be a hero.
I'm going, Q.
So if I were you,
I'd start working on a way
to set that precedent.
CHAKOTAY:
First officer's log,
supplemental.
We've laid in a course
for the point in space
where the female Q says
we can enter the Continuum
and find the captain.
You-- helm boy.
Adjust course to
heading 235 mark 08.
Increase speed
to maximum impulse.
Sir?
KIM:
Uh, commander?
What is it, Harry?
She's put us on a direct course
for another star
about to go supernova.
You did say you wanted
to get into the Continuum.
Yes, but in one piece.
Try to wrap your
minuscule mind around this:
these supernovas are actually
caused by spatial disruptions
within the Continuum--
the result of the war.
Now, each time
a star implodes,
a negative density
false vacuum is created
which actually sucks
the surrounding matter
into the Continuum.
So Voyager will be
pulled in too.
If we time it perfectly.
Otherwise,
the subsequent explosion
will blow you all
into micro-fragments.
TUVOK:
Commander.
I needn't remind you
that close proximity
to a supernova will crush us
whether or not
we time it perfectly.
( sighs )
You're so negative.
He does have a point.
Humanoids. Q to Engineering.
Go ahead, Q.
Take warp drive off-line
then remodulate the shield to
emit a beta-tachyon pulse
and prepare to emit a series
of focused anti-proton beams
to the shield bubble.
Does this make any sense
to you, B'elanna?
I'd be lying if I said
I understood it completely,
but if she's thinking
what I think she's thinking
we should increase power
to the shields by...
a factor of ten.
That's assuming, of course,
that the shield bubble
doesn't ignite
and burn us all to a crisp.
We'll be reaching
the imploding star
in 13 seconds.
I still have time
to change course.
Maintain your course.
B'elanna,
take warp drive off-line
remodulate the shields
and get ready to emit
the anti-protons.
Acknowledged.
Entering the star's corona
in three seconds.
Anti-protons now, B'elanna.
Ah, Captain Janeway I presume.
You're dismissed.
I'm sorry to have kept
you waiting, madam.
Please, sit down.
( clears throat )
I understand you walked into
our camp alone and unarmed?
That's right.
The Continuum is a dangerous
place for all us right now
not to mention
a solitary human female.
I admire your bravery.
I've come with an offer
of truce from Q.
I'm afraid the time
for diplomacy is past, madam.
If we don't end this war quickly
the damage to subspace
will be... irreversible.
Then you agree
the fighting has to stop.
Most certainly.
That's why we intend to bring
this war to a conclusion
by the most expedient
means possible.
I'm relieved to hear
you say that. May I ask how?
Quite simple,
really.
Since Q is the ringleader
of the so-called
"Freedom Faction"
We shall have to execute him.
With all due respect, sir,
there are no chapters in
the history of my own people
more tragic than wars which
set neighbor against neighbor.
Q has an idea
for a non-violent way
to bring this conflict
to an end.
I urge you to listen
to what he has to say.
We're already resolved, madam.
I'd be greatly in your debt
if you'd tell me
where we can find him.
I won't do that.
No, I didn't think you would.
Fortunately we won't be
needing your assistance.
I told you, he's willing
to negotiate, let him go.
She's right.
I've had a change of heart.
Grovel all you want, Q.
I've been waiting for this
moment for an eternity.
Put them both in chains.
Wait. What are you
charging me with?
Collaborating
with the enemy,
which, in the Continuum,
is a crime punishable....
by death.
JANEWAY:
Why won't you listen to me?
I told your commander
last night
we can resolve
this situation peacefully.
If it's any consolation, there
are those in the Continuum
who will remember us
as martyrs.
I'd rather skip
that particular honor.
Oh...
Still, you have to admit
there's something romantic
about going
to our deaths together.
Do you have any last words?
I won't plead for my own life.
From your perspective,
I know it seems insignificant,
but what is not insignificant
is the fact that the Q
as an omnipotent race
have an opportunity
to be a positive force
to set a higher standard
for other beings
in the galaxy.
I implore you all,
don't go through with this.
Don't allow yourselves
to continue using violence
to resolve
your differences.
Q, do you have anything to add?
Today, I sacrifice my existence
for the principles
of freedom and individuality
that I have fought for so long.
But this woman is innocent.
What's more she saved my life,
and she tried to save us
from each other.
Kill me if you must...
but let her go.
COLONEL Q:
It's a very touching speech, Q.
But as usual, your rhetoric
fails to compensate
for your irresponsibility.
Ready.
Aim.
I'm sorry.
I know.
COLONEL Q:
Fire!
( groans )
( moaning ): I'm hit.
I'm dying.
Q.
What?
They're not firing at us.
They're not?
CHAKOTAY:
Harry, get the captain.
Captain, are you all right?
I'm fine.
Oh, darling, I knew
you'd come for me.
Aren't you going
to untie me?
How do I know
you won't run off
with the next bi-pedal female
that catches your eye?
Well, it just so happens
I have a proposal
which will reassure
you of my devotion.
Hmm!
Put down the gun!
Think of it, Q.
We'd be visionaries,
innovators
the parents of peace.
That does have
a ring to it.
PARIS:
Captain, what should
I do with him?
Q and I have a plan to end
the war. Call off your troops.
Do as she says,
and I'll call my people off.
They may be humanoids,
but they're using our weapons.
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Tell our people
to stop shooting.
Hold your fire!
Put down your weapons.
So, darling, have you
given any thought
as to how we
might accomplish
this historic act
of procreation?
I've thought
of nothing else
since you suggested it.
( whispering )
Oh.
Oh. Oh.
( laughing )
I love it when
you talk dirty.
Why don't I give you two
some privacy?
Oh, Kathy.
Don't you
like to watch?
Oh!
Mm!
( both sigh )
I was good,
wasn't I?
Very good.
( chuckles )
That was it?
You had your chance.
Don't go crying
about it now.
Lieutenant Paris,
what's our position?
We're back
on our original course.
All crew are present
and accounted for.
Ensign Kim,
any sign of supernovas?
No, ma'am.
Nothing but calm space ahead.
Looks like
the war's over.
Mr. Chakotay, run a series
of standard diagnostics.
If everything checks out,
take us to warp six.
Aye, Captain.
I'll be in my ready room.
( Q babbling playfully )
( gasps )
Q!
He's got my cheekbones,
don't you think?
He's adorable.
I'd say fatherhood
agrees with you.
Well, I'll admit,
I... I look at the universe
in an entirely
different way now.
I mean, I can't go around
causing temporal anomalies
or subspace inversions
without considering the impact
it'll have on my son.
I'm glad to hear you intend
to set a good example.
By the way, did I tell
you how smart he is?
I've already taught him how to
knock small planets
out of orbit.
And I thought
you were going to teach him
about love and conscience.
Oh!
That's why we want
Aunty Kathy
to be the godmother now,
don't we?
I'm... honored.
Yeah, well, wait until
we ask you to baby-sit.
You can't leave
the little guy alone
for a nanosecond.
Well... it's time to be going.
The old ball and chain really
hates it when we're late.
Say bye-bye.
Bye-bye.