Good health, strong body,
clear mind.
And you.
Your hospitality,
your generosity,
your patience.
Many thanks.
My colleague's behavior...
our apologies.
Consul, I assure you,
I intended...
Please make her quiet.
Captain, please.
I understand.
Good health, strong body,
clear mind.
And you.
Your journey home
short and safe.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50425.1.
Mr. Neelix and I have completed
our three-day trade mission
with the Tak Tak,
one of the more
unusual species
we've encountered
in the Delta Quadrant.
We are en route
back to Voyager.
Oh...
I've always been taught
to be tolerant
of other cultures
and points of view--
no matter how alien--
but I have to say
that the Tak Tak
are the most
unforgiving people
I've ever met.
They are a little impatient.
They make the Klingons
look sedate.
I may never put my hands
on my hips again.
You had no way of knowing
you were making one
of the worst insults possible.
Obviously, they've never
heard of "forgive and forget."
It's a good thing you
were there, Mr. Neelix.
I might have been shot at dawn.
I have studied
chromolinguistics,
American Sign Language,
the gestural idioms
of the Leyron,
but I just couldn't get the hang
of the Tak Tak.
It seemed like more than just
a language to me, Captain.
A lot of their gestures,
from what I could tell,
were ritualistic--
you might even say
superstitious.
You have a genuine flair
for diplomacy, Mr. Neelix.
I may have to promote you...
from morale officer
to ambassador.
With all the species
we're bound to meet,
I could use a man like you
at the front door.
Ambassador Neelix.
I like the sound of that.
( console beeping )
We're approaching
the rendezvous coordinates.
Dropping to
one-quarter impulse.
Voyager's not there.
And they're not responding
to hails.
I'm running
a long-range scan.
There they are.
They're holding position
in Sector 3-8.
Coordinates 121 mark 6.
That's over a light-year
away from here.
The ship appears
to be adrift.
They could be in trouble.
Engaging maximum warp.
Janeway to Voyager.
Commander Chakotay, respond.
The ship looks
perfectly fine.
There's no sign
of any external damage.
Is there any sign
of the crew?
There's some kind
of bioelectric interference.
I can't get clear
life sign readings.
The escape pods are all in place
and there's no
indication of any recent
transporter activity.
Grab a phaser, Ambassador.
We're going to get some answers.
Still no sign of the crew,
but these sensor readings
are highly erratic.
The bioelectric field
is permeating the ship.
Where's it coming from?
I can't localize it.
Let's try accessing
the ship's internal sensors.
See if we can get
a better reading.
Same problem.
The main computer's off-line.
So is the com system.
This is strange.
One of the bio-neural gel packs
in the Mess Hall ruptured,
but most of the systems in there
seem to be functioning normally.
Let's get to the Bridge.
( instrument whirring )
Someone was doing maintenance
work on this power relay.
All the equipment
is still active,
but the work hasn't
been completed.
It's almost as if
they dropped
what they were
doing and ran.
Come on.
This certainly isn't
the welcome home
I was expecting.
Me neither, but if there was
an attack of some kind,
why didn't Chakotay
try to contact us
or send out a warning buoy?
( tricorder beeping )
I'm picking up a com signal
about ten meters ahead.
It's coming from
inside this room.
This is Ensign Wildman's
quarters.
Is she in there?
I can't tell.
Let's take a look.
Stand ready.
NEELIX:
Coming up next,
our very special guest--
Ensign Kaplan.
She's going
to be sharing her...
Here's our com signal--
your Good Morning,
Voyager program.
Ensign Wildman is one
of my most dedicated viewers.
According
to the time index,
she activated this program
approximately 11 hours ago.
Why is it still running?
The program is set
for automatic playback
until it's turned off.
The baby's missing, too.
According to the
protein decay,
I'd say Ensign Wildman
replicated this...
11 hours ago.
When we get to the Bridge,
we'll check the
communications logs.
They might tell us
whether or not...
( low-frequency buzzing )
There!
I can't tell if it's humanoid,
but it's emanating
a bioelectric field.
Whatever it is, it just
ran into a dead end.
( clanking )
Over here.
Something just punched
right through this floor panel
into the Jefferies tubes.
What is it?
Some sort of mucilaginous
compound.
High concentrations
of amino acids, proteins...
and fragments
of non-humanoid DNA.
Well, Ambassador,
I'd say we've got
an unexpected guest.
Somehow, I don't think
he's the diplomatic type.
( console beeping )
Main power is failing
and the environmental controls
are going off-line.
Systems are starting
to shut down one by one.
We'd better get to the Bridge.
Good. We've still
got auxiliary power.
Deck 1.
It's getting awfully hot
in here.
When environmental
controls fail,
heat from the warp plasma
conduits can't be vented.
Expect a heat wave
before long.
No problem.
I'm used to it.
I grew up near
the Rinax marshlands.
Our summers were the hottest
in the sector--
50 degrees Celsius,
90 percent humidity--
And the most vicious lavaflies
you've ever seen.
Summers in Indiana
were pretty similar
when I was growing up.
Except that
we had three suns,
and the lavaflies grew to be
six centimeters long.
Six centimeters, eh?
Insect repellent
was a booming business.
( crashing )
( buzzing )
There's a life-form
in the turboshaft.
I'm engaging
the manual override.
( buzzing intensifies )
Uh... Captain...
( thumping )
it sounds like our guest
has brought a few friends.
One more second.
I can't get
the pneumatic conduits to...
( loud thud )
That was no lavafly.
There's no life-form
in the tube above us.
We're getting out of here.
Are you all right?
Yes. Disgusting,
but all right.
That's the same
mucilaginous compound
we saw in the
transporter room.
Come on.
( tricorder beeping )
What is it?
Human life signs.
Very faint.
30 or more.
Where are they coming from?
Several decks above us.
I can't pinpoint the location.
Maybe the crew
is hiding from the aliens
and they set up
a defense perimeter.
Maybe.
One thing's for sure--
whoever's up there,
they're still alive.
Once we get
the main computer on line,
we'll be able to get a fix
on their location.
So hot.
My head is spinning.
You've got a high fever,
fluid in your lungs.
Lung.
That alien compound
is acting quickly.
Try to hang on.
Just three more decks.
Aye, aye, Captain...
Captain, go on
without me.
I'm not going to
leave you here, Neelix.
I can't.
I'm so dizzy.
There should be an emergency
medical kit up that tube.
I'll bring back something
to get you on your feet.
Don't go away.
( panting )
( faint buzzing )
( buzzing intensifies )
( loud buzzing )
NEELIX:
Help! Captain!
I'm coming, Neelix!
( intense buzzing )
( Neelix screaming )
Neelix!
( distant thudding )
( clattering )
( thudding )
( keypad beeping )
( buzzing )
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager
to anyone within range.
My ship has been seized
by unknown life-forms.
Require any and all assistance.
( buzzing approaching )
( console beeping )
( buzzing intensifies )
( gasps )
( console beeping )
( faint coughing )
( coughing )
( raspy moaning )
Harry...
Harry?
Chakotay.
( buzzing )
( groaning )
( coughing )
( panting )
( keypad beeps denial )
( sighs )
( grunting )
Captain.
Needless to say, I-I thought
you were something else.
It won't be long before
the other aliens sense you here
and try to invade Sick Bay.
We don't have much time
to treat you.
Doctor, what's going on?
What are tho...?
( groans )
You've ruptured
your dorsal extensor muscle
and bruised two ribs.
I'm going to have to
perform minor surgery.
Lie on your side and try to
remain perfectly still.
Oh...
Tell me what's happened.
Voyager has been infected
by a macrovirus.
A macrovirus?
A form of life I've never
encountered or even imagined.
What about the crew?
Captain...
I promise, I will tell you
exactly what happened
if you just lie still.
Shortly after you'd left
for the Tak Tak homeworld,
we received a distress call
from a nearby mining colony,
a race called the Garans.
They were experiencing
what appeared to be
a minor viral outbreak.
Fever...
disorientation.
I think it's
some kind of virus.
Nothing serious,
but if we don't stop it now,
we'll be forced
to shut down the operation.
We may be able to help you.
Doctor?
A synthetic antigen
may do the trick.
However, it will
have to be modified
for the specific virus.
I'd like to beam down
to the mining colony
and examine
a few of the infected.
An away mission.
I'm the only member of this crew
who can successfully enter
a contaminated environment
without risk.
Besides, I've been
looking forward
to spreading
my wings.
Good enough.
It'll take us about
three hours to reach you.
Thank you, Commander.
I don't think we'll...
be going anywhere.
Prepare to download
my program
into the autonomous
emitter.
Yes, Doctor.
They're not responding
to our hails.
Life signs.
There's a lot
of bioelectric interference.
I can't get a clear reading.
Perhaps their condition
is more serious
than they thought.
I better get down there.
Doctor, don't forget.
You're not invulnerable.
If anything happens
to that portable emitter,
your program could be lost.
Don't worry, Commander.
I've been studying
the Starfleet guidelines
for away-team members.
For this particular
scenario--
Medical Emergency
on Alien Terrain--
it is recommended we keep an
open com channel at all times.
You heard the man.
Channel open.
Away team to Voyager.
Transport was successful,
and my portable emitter
is working perfectly.
I am scanning the mine shaft
and proceeding on vector 1-4-7.
Ambient temperature
is 16 degrees Celsius.
Cavern illumination is minimal,
but shouldn't pose a problem
for my optical sensors.
The cave walls
are comprised of granite
with a mixture of pyroclastic...
Doctor, I appreciate
your attention to detail,
but we don't need
that much information.
Let us know when
you've found the miners.
Oh. Very well.
Stand by then.
( moaning gasps )
Voyager, I've found
one of the miners.
He appears to be suffering
from the advanced stages
of severe viral infection.
CHAKOTAY:
Can you treat him?
Not without a more specialized
immunizing agent.
This is curious.
The virus has begun
to concentrate
in a region near his neck,
and it's using
his glandular tissue
to create some sort of...
orifice.
( faint buzzing )
Something is emerging.
A life-form.
Commander, I think
I've just discovered
a completely new form of life.
From what I can tell,
it appears to be...
a macroscopic
version of the virus.
You mean the virus has grown.
Yes.
By a factor of billions.
The virus absorbed
the miner's growth hormones
into its protein structure
and used them to increase
its own mass and dimensions.
In essence,
the virus has found a way
to leave the microscopic world
and enter the macroscopic
world-- our world.
It's a remarkable
evolutionary development.
The virus appears to be
attracted to infrared radiation.
It's mistaking my holo-matrix
for body heat.
At the moment,
this one's approximately
.5 millimeters in diameter,
but it's continuing to grow
at a rate
of 30 microns every second.
Commander, permission
to beam the virus aboard
for further analysis.
No. The virus
isn't in our database.
The biofilters
might not recognize it.
You'll have to settle
for tricorder data.
Very well,
but I think I should...
( rustling )
Stand by, Voyager.
( gasping )
Hold on. Stop.
You... you've
got to help us.
I intend to, but first
I must return to my ship
and prepare an antidote.
Oh, take me with you.
I'm afraid
that's not possible.
We'd risk infecting
the crew.
You can't...
leave me.
( moaning )
Please.
Commander Chakotay,
perhaps if we established
a force field around Sick Bay
and beamed victims directly...
I'm sorry, but I'm afraid
we can't take the chance.
But these people need...
Doctor, away team guidelines
specifically forbid
the transport
of unknown infectious...
Of unknown infectious agents
onto a starship
without establishing
containment
and eradication protocols.
I understand.
I'll do my best to help you.
Away team to Voyager.
One to beam up.
Doctor to Bridge.
Checking the biofilters.
It appears
several viral organisms
were beamed up as well.
The biofilter
has isolated them.
Purge the filters.
Aye, sir.
Purging is complete.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
What I didn't realize
was that, in the few seconds it
took me to purge the filters,
some of the virus
had already migrated
into the transporter buffer.
Any luck?
I'm creating
a synthetic antigen
that will inhibit the virus'
ability to replicate,
but I haven't quite figured out
how to restore
the infected cells
to their
original condition.
As for the larger versions
of the viruses--
what I've termed
the macrovirus--
I would suggest a flyswatter.
How long
before the antigen's ready?
I'd say another 12 hours.
That gives us time
to rendezvous
with the Captain.
We'll deal with this
after she's aboard.
Commander,
I'd like to apologize
for my overzealous behavior
on the away mission.
Compassion is nothing
to be sorry about, Doctor.
It won't be the last
time you're faced
with a moral dilemma
in the field.
But if it makes you
feel any better,
your performance
was... exemplary.
Thank you.
I told you he'd understand.
Yes. You did.
We continued working
on the antigen.
Unfortunately, the macrovirus
was working faster.
It had already moved
from the transporter buffer
into an adjacent system.
B'Elanna,
thank God you're here.
The natives
are getting restless.
What's the emergency?
Well, I volunteered
to help out while Neelix
is away on the trade mission.
The heating array overloaded.
It incinerated
a 12-kilo pot roast
and all the food replicators
went off-line.
Mmm. Looks delicious.
Maybe there's a problem
with the bio-neural gel pack
in the replicator panel.
Actually...
I'm a pretty good cook when
Engineering's doing its job.
( laughs )
Oh, so this is my fault.
Well, the gel packs are
your department, aren't they?
Besides, what was
I supposed to tell
all these hungry,
irritable people?
You know, I think that there's
a plasma relay on Deck 7
that really needs repairs.
Oh, no, you can't
leave me now, Lieutenant.
Oh, you need me.
I'm touched.
What's going on here?
It looks like this gel pack
has an infection.
Half the neurodes
have been burned out
and the pack is filled with
some kind of
mucilaginous compound.
Tom, call the Doctor
and tell him...
B'Elanna.
Were any other
gel packs infected?
No. Just the one
in the Mess Hall.
The ship is healthy.
It's the crew
we have to worry about.
Your bones have healed,
but the surrounding tissue
will be sensitive
for a few days.
( groaning )
It's getting warmer in here.
I'm afraid it's not
just the ship, Captain.
It's also you.
You've been infected
with the macrovirus.
You're experiencing
a high fever.
Yes, on the Bridge, I was
bitten by one of them.
Your glandular system
is already being affected.
If I don't treat you now,
you'll end up like
the rest of the crew.
I've spent the past few hours
perfecting the antigen...
but I haven't tested it
on a live subject yet.
Looks like I'll have to be
your guinea pig, Doctor.
The crew-- why are they
all in the Mess Hall
and the cargo bays?
I believe
the larger macroviruses
are driven
by some sort of instinct
to assemble
their host population.
Tell me what happened
after B'Elanna was exposed
to the infected gel pack.
I was faced
with an imminent epidemic.
Oh, no.
Doctor to the Bridge.
The macrovirus
is on board Voyager
and appears to be... airborne.
I suggest a level-4 quarantine
of the Mess Hall
and all adjoining sections.
Acknowledged. Red Alert.
Initiate level-4 quarantine
protocols on Deck 2.
Aye, sir.
All hands,
this is Commander Chakotay.
We've detected an airborne virus
in the Mess Hall.
Deck 2 is under quarantine.
No crew member--
repeat--no crew member
is to leave or enter
any section on Deck 2.
Stand by for further
instructions.
I've erected
the biocontainment fields.
The area has been sealed.
DOCTOR:
We managed to avoid
a shipwide outbreak,
but every crew member on Deck 2
had been contaminated.
I collected a single live
specimen of the macrovirus
and returned to Sick Bay
in hopes of finding a cure.
Ready, Doctor.
Optimal magnification.
The specimen
has synthesized
B'Elanna's growth hormone
into its own structure.
Excellent.
That should give us
the information we need
to destroy the virus
without killing
its host cells.
The virus has grown
by 150 microns.
Its rate of growth
shouldn't hinder our analysis,
as long as its genetic structure
stays the same.
Doctor...
Computer, erect
a level-3 force field
around the microscope station.
( groaning )
Well, so much for lunch.
( moaning )
I may never look
at food again.
I thought Klingons
didn't get nauseated.
You have
a redundant stomach.
Well, right now...
they're both unhappy.
( groaning )
Paris to Sick Bay.
DOCTOR:
Go ahead, Lieutenant.
I just saw two macroviruses
come out of B'Elanna's neck.
Stand by, Mr. Paris.
We're close to formulating
an antigen.
The virus has grown
to .3 meters.
On the microscopic level,
the virus uses that
needle-like projection
to penetrate a cell membrane.
On our level,
it probably impales
its victim
in much the same way
infusing him
with its own genetic code.
( beeping )
The antigen is ready.
Kes...
Computer,
deactivate force field.
( buzzing angrily )
( hypospray whooshes )
Well...
one down, ten billion to go.
Eager to inoculate
those already infected,
I quickly headed
for the quarantined area.
Though their condition
had grown worse,
it was the least
of our problems.
Lieutenant...
if you can hear me,
I'm going to give you
an injection.
It should eliminate
the virus.
What? What is that?
( low-pitched buzzing )
You don't want to know.
Doctor to the Bridge.
Intruder alert.
Deck 2, Section 13.
Within minutes,
dozens of the larger organisms
forced their way beyond Deck 2
and overwhelmed the ship.
It wasn't long before
the crew was incapacitated.
Although I've developed
an effective vaccine,
I can't administer it.
Every time I try to get
to the crew, I'm attacked.
Perhaps with your help.
How many of the larger
macroviruses are there?
I have no way of knowing.
Dozens, perhaps hundreds.
They're replicating
at an exponential rate.
By this time tomorrow,
there could be thousands.
( low-pitched buzzing,
thumping )
Speak of the devil.
You're cured.
The question is:
How do we cure
the rest of the crew?
This antigen--
can it be distributed
in a gaseous form?
For absorption via
the respiratory system?
I've already considered
dispensing it
through environmental
controls.
But they're off-line
and I have limited
engineering expertise.
Leave that to me.
All we have to do
is get to Environmental Control
on Deck 12.
Easier said than done.
We'll run into the same problem
I faced
when I tried to get
to the Mess Hall.
Not if I can help it.
Prepare two canisters
of antigen.
We'll split up and
take different routes
to Environmental Control.
It'll double
our chances.
If you get there first,
call me,
and I'll talk you through
the repairs.
The macroviruses are attracted
to infrared radiation.
Set your tricorder to emit
a thermal scattering signal.
It will make it more difficult
to target you.
Ready when you are.
( buzzing
and thumping continue)
We'll be right with you.
Take Jefferies Tube 11.
What's wrong?
I've been studying
the ship's infrastructure
and I'm familiar
with most of it,
but how do I get
there from here?
Jefferies Tube 11.
Take a left at Section 31.
Head straight down
past the tractor beam emitter
until you hit Deck 10.
Get out at Section 3
and follow the corridor
all the way around...
Until I hit
the shuttle bay.
Then I crawl through
Access Port 9,
go past three airlocks
and then two decks down.
Environmental Control's
at the end of the hall.
Now I remember.
Who designed this ship,
anyway?
Good luck.
( distant thumping and buzzing)
( groaning )
( buzzing approaching )
Doctor to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
I won't be joining you
as soon as I'd hoped.
The macroviruses overwhelmed me
on Deck 10
and my portable emitter
was nearly destroyed.
I've taken refuge inside the
shuttle bay in a shuttlecraft.
Stay put, Doctor.
I'm close
to environmental control.
Janeway to Doctor.
I've got the environmental
controls back on line.
Set the dispersal nodes
to one part per thousand.
What's going on?
I'm not sure, but I think
someone's firing at Voyager.
Doctor,
use the shuttle's sensors
to find out what's happening
and patch the data to me.
Aye, Captain.
It's the Tak Tak.
Doctor, open a channel
and hail their captain.
Stand by.
Consul, this is
Captain Janeway.
Why are you
firing at us?
The Garan mining colony,
infected.
We purified them.
Your distress call received.
Voyager infected.
We are purifying you.
Purifying?
You're trying to destroy us.
No choice.
No cure for the virus.
Voyager's existence a threat.
Your illness.
Our apologies.
Wait.
We've developed a cure.
But your torpedoes
just stopped us
from getting it to our crew
and putting an end to this.
Cure?
Yes. A synthetic antigen.
We've tested it and it works.
I can prove it to you.
And I'd be willing to share
the antigen with your people,
but first, you've got to
stop attacking my ship.
Give me a chance
to save my crew.
A chance.
One hour.
( console beeps )
Doctor, we've got a problem.
That last torpedo destroyed
the secondary power couplings.
I can't get the environmental
controls back online.
( thumping and thudding )
We appear to be
low on options.
The only systems
we still have access to
are the ones
with independent power sources--
shuttlecraft, life-support,
the holodecks...
Doctor,
you said the macroviruses
are attracted
to infrared signatures.
That's right.
Right now, you and I are
the only targets left on board.
What if we gave them something
new to sink their teeth into?
What are you suggesting?
( steel drum music playing )
( conversation and laughter )
( buzzing approaching )
( screaming )
( console beeping )
Doctor, it seems to be working.
I've programmed
the holo-characters
to react to the viruses.
We don't have much time.
Grab your hypospray
and get to the crew.
You've got a clear path
to the Mess Hall
and both cargo bays.
Acknowledged.
What about you, Captain?
I've put together what you
might call an "antigen bomb."
Now all I have to do
is drop it.
( distant buzzing )
( buzzing intensifies )
( buzzing stops )
Doctor to Captain Janeway.
Captain, please respond.
Go ahead.
It worked. The macroviruses
have been destroyed.
And the ship?
There was heavy damage
suffered on Holodeck 2,
but there are
no hull breaches in evidence.
Astonishment.
Your vessel, purified.
And we'd be willing to share
the cure with you
if you'd be kind enough
to forego destroying our ship.
Of course, of course.
Purification will cease.
My word.
Many thanks,
Captain of Voyager.
Good health.
( sighs )
( soft jazz playing )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Good morning, Captain.
Here's an update
on repairs.
How's the crew holding up?
They're fine, although
the doctor tells me
a few people are still
reporting post-viral queasiness.
I'm not surprised.
Inform the crew I'm granting
extended R&amp;R for all personnel
and work out
the shift rotations.
Aye, Captain.
Speaking of R&amp;R...
a few of us are going skiing
on the holodeck--
the Ktarian glaciers.
Fresh air, good workout.
Care to join us?
No, thank you, but have fun.
Not your cup of tea?
Oh, on the contrary.
I love to ski.
Let's just say...
I've had enough of a workout
for the time being.
Understood.
( sighs )
( pencil scraping )