Mr. Tuvok,
Mr. Tuvok!
I was supposed
to accompany you
on security rounds
this morning.
Did you forget?
I was not aware that we
had a definite appointment.
I'm sure
it was definite.
Well, maybe not
completely definite.
That is,
I'd expressed my desire
to "learn the ropes,"
as it were,
and I have
completed my study
of starship
security protocols.
I think you'll find
that I'm fully qualified
to serve in the capacity
of a Starfleet
security officer.
Junior grade,
of course.
If you will recall,
Mr. Neelix,
I did not guarantee you
a position.
But Captain Janeway
is always saying
that Voyager is
a ship of opportunity.
That is true, but
opportunities for promotion
on a starship
must be earned.
I've been working
hard at this.
I really do feel
I have a great deal
to contribute to Voyager
beyond my current role.
Your dedication is duly noted,
Mr. Neelix.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I am due on the Bridge.
I'll see you first thing
tomorrow morning
for security rounds.
Ensign Vorik.
Get me a duotronic probe.
I'm having trouble
regulating the plasma flow.
May I suggest a gravitic
caliper instead?
You might find it a more
precise instrument.
Good idea,
but bring me both.
Good morning,
B'Elanna.
You missed my special
Klingon breakfast buffet.
I'm sorry, Neelix,
but a bowl of cold gagh
is not my idea of how
to start a morning.
Well, you're not alone.
None of the crew
seemed especially
enthusiastic about it.
Um, what's
the problem with...
the plasma injectors?
I've been getting
myself up to speed
on Federation
warp propulsion.
The plasma flow
in the manifold
seems to be constricted.
Ah! Have you thought
of phase-locking them
to the dilithium matrix?
That was the first
thing I did.
Oh.
I really am interested
in learning more about
engineering systems,
maybe even volunteering
for a few duty shifts.
In fact, I have
a couple of questions
about the impulse
response filters...
Neelix, Neelix,
this really isn't
a good time.
I understand,
Lieutenant.
Sorry.
I'll just, uh, watch for a while
if you don't mind.
Here are the tools, sir.
I also had a question
about the transporter buffers...
JANEWAY:
Mr. Neelix, please
report to the Bridge.
On my way, Captain.
Neelix, we seem
to be approaching
some kind of interstellar
dust clouds.
Can you tell us
anything about them?
They look rather
ominous to me.
I believe this is
a region of space
known as
the Nekrit Expanse.
JANEWAY:
What can you tell us
about this Expanse,
Mr. Neelix?
It's a vast territory.
No one knows much
about it.
Those plasma storms
might be a problem
for navigation.
Full sensor scan, Tuvok.
Aye, Captain.
Can we plot a course around it?
That might be advisable.
I don't believe so.
It's thousands
of light-years wide.
Then we'll have
to go through it.
Looks like we'll
be counting
on your knowledge
of the Delta Quadrant
even more than
usual, Neelix.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm at your command,
as always.
Will there be any
planets where we can
take on supplies?
There is a station
near the border...
a kind of supply depot
for mining and trading ships.
I suggest we stop there
for provisions
before we go
into the Nekrit Expanse.
What are the
coordinates?
Uh, let's see.
It's actually been a while...
CHAKOTAY:
I have the station
on sensors, Captain.
3.4 light-years away,
heading 071 mark 17.
You heard him, Tom.
On our way.
We're being hailed, Captain.
On screen.
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
Bahrat,
manager of this station.
What can I do for you?
Your station is
a trading outpost, isn't it?
I'd like permission
to come aboard
to negotiate for supplies.
Granted,
but understand
that any transaction
you negotiate on this station
is subject to my approval.
I receive a 20 percent
commission on all trade.
Your whereabouts
will be closely monitored.
Communications with your ship
may also be monitored
at my discretion.
Do you agree
to these conditions?
Evidently, I have no choice.
Excellent.
Meet me in my office
in one hour
and we'll discuss your needs.
Pleasant fellow.
Neelix, Chakotay, Tom,
you're with me.
( monitor beeping )
( door opens )
Mr. Bahrat.
What is it?
I'm Kathryn Janeway.
I've brought a list
of the supplies we'll need.
Forgive me,
but it's demanding work
watching over this station.
We get all kinds
of troublemakers here.
I understand.
All right. Let's see it.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm... pergium?
To regenerate the filters
in our environmental
control system.
That might be
a little difficult.
It's a rare commodity.
Give me a few moments
and I'll put together a list
of potential suppliers,
but I'll warn you,
they won't strike easy bargains.
I'm prepared to deal fairly.
( buzz of conversation,
whir of machinery )
Good day, gentlemen.
Good day.
Anything in particular
you're looking for?
Anything I can
help you with?
We were hoping to find
some magnetic spindle bearings
for our reaction
control assembly.
Spindle bearings,
spindle bearings...
No. Can't help you
with that. No.
Long voyage ahead?
Uh, you could say that.
I have something
that might ease your journey,
ease it considerably.
Rhuludian crystals.
Ingesting just one of these
will make days of tedious travel
seem like moments
of exquisite rapture.
No, thank you.
The price is surprisingly...
No.
Nice place.
I see you're
a map dealer.
I have coordinate charts
for all of the local
mining colonies.
Actually,
I'm interested
in maps of the Nekrit Expanse.
You must be a stranger
here or you'd know.
There aren't any maps
of that region.
Surely, there's an astrometric
chart or a database
that would help me plot
a safe course.
The Nekrit Expanse is
too unstable to chart.
MALE:
No matter.
He never could plot
a straight course anyway.
Wixiban?
Wix, is that you?
( laughs )
I can't believe it.
What are you doing here?
I've never seen
another Talaxian
this far from home.
It's a long story.
I'm one of the crew
of a highly-advanced starship.
Ah... I want to
hear all about it.
Come on.
The tavern here serves
the best Toffa ale
I've had in years.
NEELIX:
I do a little
of everything.
Cook, guide,
advisor to the Captain.
Possibly even
an unofficial ambassador.
( chuckling ):
Life's been good to you.
Yes, I'm very... I'm very lucky.
Mmm... but what about you?
What are you doing
on this station?
A little of this,
a little of that.
To tell you the truth,
things haven't gone
quite so well for me.
I'm sorry.
Ever since that nasty business
with the Ubeans,
things have
been difficult.
But you know me.
Can't keep Wix down long.
I'm working on a trade deal now
that should put me right back
in the thick of things again.
I hope it works out.
Yeah.
Uh, Wix...
about the Ubeans.
I don't think I ever told you
how much I valued what you did.
You'd have done the same for me.
Yes, I would have, but you
were the one who got caught.
I owe you a great deal.
If there's anything
I can do to help...
I'm fine. Honestly.
Maybe not on the crew
of a magnificent starship,
but I'll get by.
To tell you the truth, um...
it's not quite
what I told you.
In fact, I may not be
on Voyager much longer.
Why?
The main reason Captain Janeway
needed me was as a guide
to give her information
about this Quadrant,
but I've never been
beyond the Nekrit Expanse.
I can't tell her anything
about what's ahead.
But your other jobs,
cook, ambassador...?
They don't really need a cook
and I don't think our Captain
really requires an ambassador.
I've tried to find
some other area
where I might be useful, but...
the truth is...
I'm not needed.
I'm hoping you can help me.
I can't let Voyager go
into that dangerous part
of space
without some idea
of what's there.
I have to find a map.
Hmm.
( clattering )
Can I be of help,
Mr. Neelix?
Dinner isn't for another
hour, Ensign Vorik,
and I don't have time
to prepare a snack.
I don't require food
at the moment.
Lieutenant Torres
sent me to adjust
the control interface
in your food replicators.
You said you were experiencing
difficulties with them.
Oh, of course.
Go ahead.
Neelix...
I thought you'd like
to say hello to your old friend.
Well, uh...
yes, yes, of course.
So, this is where you prepare
your legendary feasts.
Well...
You know, Commander,
Neelix has
more varied talents
than anyone I've ever known.
You're lucky to have him
on board.
Mr. Wix was able to find
those magnetic spindle bearings
we were looking for.
I don't know what we'd have done
if he hadn't come up with them.
Well, yes, Wix has
always had a knack
for finding
those hard-to-locate items.
( chuckles )
I'll let you two
reminisce for a while.
Thanks again, Wix.
You're more than welcome.
Yes, this is
the mess room.
On any given day,
I must be prepared
to feed over
a hundred people.
About done, Ensign?
Not quite.
Well, I really don't need
the replicators today,
so you can finish later.
As you wish.
Oh, and remind
Lieutenant Torres,
uh, when she has a moment,
I'd still like to go over
a few things with her.
I'll relay the message.
NEELIX:
Thank you.
Wix...
please tell me
those spindle bearings
weren't stolen property.
Of course not.
I wouldn't do that to you.
Neelix, I need the work.
I don't live
on a comfortable starship.
No one looks out for me
except me.
Maybe you've forgotten
what that feels like.
I haven't forgotten.
I've been stuck
on that trash-heap
of a space station
for three years.
My ship's been impounded.
I can't afford to give Bahrat
what he wants to get it back.
Do you begrudge me
an opportunity
to make a fair trade?
Of course not.
I have news for you.
I've located some pergium
for your ship.
That's great news.
Captain Janeway
hasn't had any luck.
And I've found someone
with a map.
Wonderful!
How do we get it?
It'll involve several
bartering sessions.
I have the opportunity
to sell medical supplies
to an outpost
whose people are dying
of a lung disease.
It's a good cause
and it will make me enough
to pay Bahrat
and get my ship back.
Where does the map come in?
When I deliver
the medical supplies,
one of the physicians will
give me an astrometric chart.
I can't thank you enough.
I'll have to ask
your help though.
We'll need a shuttle.
First, we have to get
to a nearby freighter
to pick up
the medical supplies.
Then, we return
to the space station
and meet with one of the
physicians from the outpost.
With your transporter
technology,
we could be in and out
of the station within minutes.
Then, I could finally
get away from here
and get back
to a Talaxian colony.
I don't think that
would be a problem.
Just one thing.
Don't tell anyone
that we're delivering
medical supplies
to the station.
Not even one person.
If Bahrat finds out,
he'll take 20 percent
and I can't afford that.
I-I suppose there's
no need to mention it.
Thanks, Neelix.
I knew I could
count on you.
Didn't I tell you
this would be easy?
( chortles )
I got the medical supplies
and you got the pergium
your ship needs so badly.
Only 20 kilograms. I told
Commander Chakotay
it would be 45.
You're lucky to get
what you did.
Come on, Neelix.
A few minutes more
and we'll be done.
And you'll have a map
to help you through
the Nekrit Expanse.
What is the matter with you?
I don't like keeping the whole
truth from Commander Chakotay.
It's not honest.
I don't remember you
ever being so squeamish
about twisting the truth.
Wix...
I'm not what I used to be.
Neither am I.
We've both tried
to change our lives.
You've done it.
Now, I have the same chance.
We're almost there.
We should have your transporter
take us to Corridor 14-L
near the outer docking ports.
It's hardly ever used.
Our contact
will meet us there.
We're within
transporter range.
I've entered
the coordinates.
What are you doing?!
This station
is a dangerous place
and these supplies
are valuable.
We have to be able
to defend ourselves.
You said this
would be easy.
It's just a precaution.
Let's go.
Computer, energize.
( whispering ):
Where's your contact?
He'll be here. Don't worry.
I don't like this,
meeting in dark passageways
late at night.
MALE:
Wix.
Sutok.
This is my associate.
You have the supplies?
As promised.
What's he doing?
Satisfied?
Completely.
What kind of medical
supplies are those?
If you give me my payment,
we'll be on our way.
Yes, I have it right here.
( groans )
Stop them! Get his weapon!
Wix!
( grunts )
Someone's coming!
( alarm blaring )
Neelix!
Get us out of here.
Computer,
two to beam up.
NEELIX:
You lied to me
from the beginning!
And I was foolish enough
to believe you.
It should have been
as easy as I said.
I didn't know Sutok
would try to steal the tubes.
Those aren't ordinary
medical supplies.
You failed to
mention that.
They do have
a medicinal application,
but no one would pay
what I was supposed to get
if they were just
simple medications.
They're narcotics,
aren't they?
Oh, you're up to
your same old tricks.
We have to talk
to Captain Janeway
as soon as we get back.
Do you really
want to do that?
How is it going to look
to your shipmates
when they find out you were
once a contraband smuggler
and that you
were involved
in this ugly
business tonight?
You think your position
on Voyager is precarious now?
Wait till they discover
the whole truth
about you.
I can't just
forget about this.
So you'd let Bahrat put me
in cryostatic suspension?
I guess you would.
You did let me spend a year
in that Ubean prison.
Wix...
I never told you what it
was like in there, did I?
About eating worms
to stay alive...
sleeping in a cell
where the vermin
chew on you all night...
being punished in ways
you couldn't imagine.
All right!
I won't say anything.
But I don't want to have
anything more to do with you.
The debt is paid.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I have called a meeting
of the senior staff
to inform them
of some very disturbing news
I have just received.
There's been a murder
aboard the station.
CHAKOTAY:
A murder?
I've been told that's not
an uncommon occurrence here.
The man who died has been
suspected of criminal activity.
Mr. Bahrat, however, discovered
something at the scene
of the killing that
greatly concerns me.
During my investigation,
I discovered some energy
readings I couldn't identify,
so I ran a spectral analysis.
He showed me the analysis
just a few minutes ago.
It's a Federation
phaser signature.
Tuvok will be
assisting Mr. Bahrat
in his investigation.
I want to know how a weapon
from Voyager
could have been involved
in this incident.
The shooting took place
in an abandoned section
of the station.
Security scanners
were disabled.
I'm reviewing other surveillance
records,
looking for anything
that might help me apprehend
whoever did this.
I've promised Mr. Bahrat
the full cooperation
of every member of this crew
during his investigation.
Dismissed.
You wanted
to see me, Mr. Tuvok?
Please, sit down.
I examined the scene
of the shooting
and confirmed the Federation
weapon signature.
A type-2 phaser blast.
Fourteen Voyager crew members
were off the ship
at the time
of the incident.
I see.
Several traders from the station
were aboard Voyager
on the day of the incident.
We can't rule out
the possibility
that one of them managed
to steal a phaser.
I suppose not.
What can you tell me
about your friend Wixiban?
Wix?
Mr. Chakotay reported
that he was aboard Voyager.
Ah, yes. He delivered
some magnetic bearings.
We're more like acquaintances,
not friends really.
I haven't seen him in years.
Has he ever been involved
in criminal activity?
I-I wouldn't know.
I certainly don't think so.
I must question him
and I would appreciate
your accompanying me.
Me?
What could I do?
You may be able to help me
evaluate
the verisimilitude
of his answers.
I see.
Please meet me
in Transporter Room 2
at 1800 hours.
How much time did you spend
aboard Voyager?
Probably less than
an hour altogether.
Were you ever alone
on the ship?
No. I was met
by Mr. Chakotay
in your
transporter room.
Extraordinary
experience
that transporter
of yours.
We delivered the bearings
to Lieutenant Torres.
Then, Mr. Chakotay
and I paid a visit
to my old friend Neelix
in your Mess Hall.
Where were you
at the time of the shooting?
In bed, asleep.
Can anyone corroborate that?
Alas, Mr. Tuvok, I sleep alone.
That will be all
for now, Mr. Wix.
I'd like to stay
for a glass of Toffa ale.
As you wish,
but please see me
as soon as you return
to the ship.
Yeah.
I'd forgotten
how easy it is
for you to lie.
You're not suggesting
I tell him the truth.
Vulcans aren't as easily fooled
as you might think.
If you want to worry,
I'll give you something
to worry about.
What?
The people I was conducting
that transaction for
aren't happy that they
didn't get paid.
I thought this was your scheme.
Do you think I could have
afforded those tubes?
I was acting as an agent
for some Kolaati Traders.
Do you know anything
about the Kolaati?
They're mean
as fire snakes.
They will kill us,
and it won't be quick.
I... I can't believe
this is happening.
Why did I ever listen to you?!
Neelix, it's all right.
I've convinced them to take
something else in payment.
Something easily come by.
They know
about Voyager.
They want a sample
of your ship's warp plasma.
They'll be able
to use it
to increase the efficiency
of their engines.
No. It's wrong.
I won't do it.
This has to stop.
You should have thought
of that in the beginning.
You're in too deeply now.
The people on Voyager
are my friends.
I can't steal from them.
Friends?
You've already told me
they're ready to put
you off the ship.
You're living
in a dream world.
It's time to wake up.
You're on your own,
just as I am
and you're going to die
a horrible death
at the hands
of the Kolaati
unless you bring them
three grams of warp plasma.
Do you understand that?
I've already told them
you'd do it.
Meet me here tomorrow morning
at 900 hours.
Hey, Neelix, what's up?
Oh, nothing.
Just thought I might
give you a hand with...
whatever it is
you're doing.
You may regret that.
Chakotay and I
have to pick up
a supply of biomimetic
gel tomorrow morning
and I am trying
to find the container
that is listed as the proper
transport device.
Starfleet standard
issue L647X7.
Well, sounds like another
set of eyes wouldn't hurt.
M-34...
No, not that one.
L647...
No, it's Y-6.
Tom...
if it's not too bold of me,
I wonder if I could
ask you something.
Sure. Anything.
I've heard you were
in some trouble in the past.
Spent time in prison.
That's right.
Do you...?
Would you... tell me
how you got in trouble?
I've thought a lot
about that
and it comes down
to one simple fact.
I didn't tell the truth.
I made a mistake,
which happens to people,
but if I'd admitted
that mistake,
it would have been
a lot better.
But I lied about it
and it nearly
ruined my life.
Why do you ask?
Oh... no reason.
Just wondered.
Here's your container.
Oh.
( laughing )
After I'm done here,
a bunch of us are going to go
down to the resort.
Why don't you come along?
Thanks, but I'm going
to turn in early.
Maybe another time.
Okay.
Good evening, Ensign.
Mr. Neelix.
I thought I'd log
a little time
in the Jefferies tubes
if that's all right.
I was unaware you
were officially
on an engineering
work detail.
Oh, it's not official,
not at all.
But Lieutenant Torres
has been good enough
to allow me to poke
around here and there,
as time permits, of course.
She has mentioned
your desire to become
familiar with Starfleet
engineering protocols.
I see no reason why
you can't proceed.
Thank you.
Ensign Vorik.
Yes, Mr. Neelix?
You're quite young.
Is it difficult for you
being so far away
from everything that's familiar?
Had I been given the choice,
I might not have chosen
to explore the Delta Quadrant.
However, since we are here,
I must say the challenges
are intriguing.
Voyager is
a wonderful place to be.
The people here
are very fortunate.
I would concur.
Did you get it?
Where is it?
I have to talk to you.
Give it to me.
I didn't get
the warp plasma.
What?!
I couldn't do it.
I just couldn't.
We have to tell the truth.
It's the only way
to make things right.
We're dead men, Neelix.
No. I have a plan.
BAHRAT:
You two,
stay where you are!
Don't panic. Stay calm.
I said stay
where you are!
What is this?
You two are
under arrest.
PARIS: Arrest?
What's the charge?
Conspiring with known
drug traffickers...
and murder.
Let's go!
This is the criminal
who was killed...
and these are the two men we
arrested.
You can't seriously regard this
as viable evidence.
I realize it's circumstantial,
but it is compelling.
It proves absolutely nothing.
It proves your two men
had a conversation
with a narcotics dealer
only hours before he was killed.
As the Captain said,
that proves nothing.
I'm holding them
for questioning.
They are
prime suspects.
I want my security officer
present
during all interrogations.
I'll take that
into consideration.
But make no mistake
about this.
Someone will serve 50 years
of cryostatic suspension
for that murder.
If I were to let
this go unpunished,
there would be anarchy
on this station within days.
You make no mistake
about this.
I won't allow members
of my crew to be condemned
for a crime
they did not commit.
( sighs )
This has gone too far.
We have to go to Bahrat.
We'll end up in his
cryostatic prison for decades.
Not if he agrees
to my plan.
Your plan is crazy.
It's worse than prison.
It's a death sentence.
That would be better
than living a lie.
I'm going whether
you do or not.
Neelix.
We've been through
too much together.
I can't let you
do this alone.
It was a type-2 Federation
phaser that was used.
It's on one of our shuttles.
You can get it
from our security officer
to verify the energy signature.
Which of you
fired the weapon?
We were both involved
in all aspects of the crime.
I was the one
with the weapon,
but I fired
in self-defense.
So you see,
Commander Chakotay
and Lieutenant Paris
are innocent.
The punishment
for trafficking
in illicit substances
is 50 years of
cryostatic imprisonment.
Your cryostatic prison
isn't a particularly
effective deterrent, is it?
It certainly is.
There's very little narcotics
trafficking that goes on here.
That's what you think.
The Kolaati have made a fortune
trading drugs here.
I know everything
that happens on this station.
Apparently not.
Since we were able
to deliver narcotics
to known criminals
right under your nose.
WIXIBAN:
They have ways of disabling
your surveillance systems.
Masking your sensors.
Creating false
visual signals.
It happens almost
every night.
I'll put a stop to that.
Since you don't know
how they do it,
that might
prove difficult.
But... we have a plan.
The Kolaati want a sample
of warp plasma from Voyager.
I'll arrange a
meeting with them
to deliver the plasma.
When they arrive, we'll
take them into custody.
How do you plan to do that?
You won't be able
to carry weapons
and if they thought
my men and I were near,
they'd be gone in a second.
We have some ideas.
If we are able
to turn them over to you,
will you agree
not to charge us with a crime?
It's no risk to me.
You'll undoubtedly perish
in this ridiculous scheme.
You'll have to provide us
with a sample
of warp plasma.
I won't take any from Voyager.
What I can give you
won't be of the same quality.
Doesn't matter.
We'll make do.
All right.
We'll try it.
But I don't hold any hopes
that you will survive.
It's been over 20 minutes.
Where are they?
I confirmed the
time and place.
They should be here.
Maybe they've
realized it's a trap.
Maybe they're not
going to show up.
Let's hope they do or we will
end up in Bahrat's prison.
It looks like somebody's
begun transmitting
a false visual signal.
My guess is they're
about to come aboard.
We'll give them five minutes
and then move in.
It's Tosin.
Who?
He's one of the most
powerful Kolaati.
Good evening, gentlemen.
My name is Neelix, and I am--
The warp plasma. Where is it?
It's right in here,
Tosin,
but first, you must
guarantee us--
You'll live for today.
No guarantees
about tomorrow.
Give me the plasma.
Slowly.
( instrument beeping )
Twenty parts per million
isonucleic residue.
This is contaminated.
You promised me a pure sample.
It really doesn't matter,
because you're under arrest.
What?
I said
you're being taken into custody
for smuggling contraband
and narcotic substances.
Very serious offenses
aboard this station,
Mr. Tosin. It's time
you faced up to them.
( laughing )
( laughter continues )
Little man...
your days have ended.
I wouldn't fire that weapon
if I were you.
That plasma canister
you're holding...
I disengaged the safety nodes
just as you came in.
Even as we speak,
warp plasma is leaking from it.
This section
of the station is filling
with plasma particles.
Fire your weapon
and you'll set off an explosion
that would undoubtedly
kill us all.
He's telling the truth, Tosin.
Don't do it.
And I wouldn't activate
your transporter system,
if I were you.
The beam would also
destabilize the plasma.
Same effect. Boom.
Then you will die with me,
little man.
No problem at all
if it means getting rid
of an Orillian lung maggot
like you.
( growls )
Go ahead.
You'd be doing me a favor.
I have nothing to lose.
Fire away.
Neelix.
Shoot.
What are you waiting for?
( breathing heavily )
Fire.
Re-engage the safety nodes.
Don't bother.
Put down your weapons.
You're under arrest
for violating Station Code 4279,
Subsection
Beta-325.
No, don't!
( screaming )
( groans )
I'm in Sick Bay?
Yes, Mr. Neelix.
You sustained
third-degree plasma burns
and a moderate concussion,
but my skills
have prevented you
from suffering permanent damage.
Thank you, Doctor.
One of the criminals was killed
in the plasma explosion.
The others have been taken
into custody by Mr. Bahrat.
Chakotay and Tom
were released.
Oh, good.
And Wix?
Mr. Wixiban
was given his shuttle.
He sent you his thanks
before making
a hasty departure.
Would all of you
excuse us please?
I'd like to talk
to Neelix alone.
Well, do you have anything
to say for yourself?
Only that I'm terribly sorry.
Oh. You're sorry.
Is that supposed
to make everything better?
I don't really care
whether you're sorry
or not, Neelix.
At this point it
doesn't matter.
I can't imagine
what could have
made you behave
the way you did.
Lying to us.
Sneaking around
behind our backs.
Covering up
criminal activity.
Did you have
some misguided reason
to think that this was
acceptable behavior?
No, ma'am.
You've been one
of my most trusted advisors
since we began this journey.
How can I ever trust you again?
How can I ever
listen to you
without wondering whether you're
telling the truth or not?
I've never been
dishonest to you before.
I swear, Captain.
I-I just took one step,
a step that seemed
perfectly reasonable,
and that step led to another and
another and before I knew it,
I was involved in something
I didn't know how to handle.
What was it?
What was so important
that you were willing
to throw away your principles?
I needed a map.
A map?
Captain, my usefulness
to you was at an end.
I don't know anything about
space beyond this point.
I couldn't let you go
into the Nekrit Expanse
without knowing
what you faced.
You've been on this ship
for two years.
I'd think by now
you'd have learned
that the first duty
of any Starfleet officer
is the truth.
You violated that duty, Neelix,
and there will be consequences.
I'm prepared to leave
the ship, Captain.
Oh, no.
It's not that easy.
You can't just walk away
from your responsibilities
because you made a mistake.
You're part of a family now,
and you have obligations.
But... I can't guide you.
I can't advise you.
I don't know what's coming.
That's not the point.
Is it?
None of us knows what's coming.
That's what Starfleet
is all about.
We are all in this
together, Neelix,
and we have to be able
to count on each other
no matter how hard it gets.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
Well, that's good.
Report to deuterium
maintenance
at 0400 tomorrow morning.
You're going to spend
the next two weeks
scrubbing the exhaust manifolds.
That should give you time
to think about what I've said.
Dismissed.