JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
stardate 50460.3.
We've been investigating
an "inversion nebula"
for several days.
This phenomenon has never been
seen in the Alpha Quadrant
and is proving something
of a mystery to us here.
According to
Federation astro-theorists,
inversion nebulae
are so unstable,
they're supposed to burn out
within a few years, but...
this one appears
to be centuries old.
Maybe the theorists
were wrong.
They never had a chance
to look at the real thing.
Not entirely wrong.
These plasma strands
we're approaching
look ready to ignite.
Tom, back us off
2,000 kilometers.
That will give us
a safety margin.
Aye, captain.
Harry, set the sensors
for full-spectrum scans,
continuous sweep.
If that nebula does flare up,
I don't want to miss a beat.
Mr. Kim, I need your attention
on the sensors.
Sorry, captain.
Full-spectrum scans.
I'm on it.
Astro-theory never predicted
this would be so lovely.
Beauty and mystery--
a tantalizing combination.
No argument here.
Right, Tuvok?
I am fully capable
of appreciating this phenomenon
without the extraneous
sentimentality
humans find so necessary.
Being moved by an emotion
isn't always extraneous.
Sometimes it's the whole point.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Mr. Kim.
Can I help you?
Um...
that's kal-toh, isn't it?
Vulcan chess?
Kal-toh is to chess
as chess is
to tic-tac-toe.
I should have known. Uh...
What is on your
mind, ensign?
Tuvok, I need your help.
I want to eliminate emotions
like Vulcans do.
Mr. Kim, it is a
lifelong process.
I realize that,
and I also know
that Vulcans use
certain techniques.
The t'an s'at,
the intellectual
deconstruction
of emotional patterns.
I'm willing to learn.
May I ask why?
I have...
feelings
I don't want to have.
That would seem
to be self-evident.
And what is the nature
of those feelings?
I... I'm in love
and I don't want to be.
I see.
And who is the object
of your affections?
Her name is... Marayna.
I am not aware of anyone
on the ship with that name.
She's not a member of the crew.
She's a character
on the holodeck.
You're in love
with a computer subroutine?
That's the problem.
Interesting.
To see through an
emotional complex
is to rob it
of its power.
The first step is to
identify the complex
in which you
have been caught.
I told you, I'm in love.
There are many different
kinds of love, ensign.
You must learn
to differentiate.
For example, you told me
that you met this individual
only days ago, yet
you feel overwhelmed.
I can't get her out of my mind,
not for a second.
Have you been
able to sleep?
No.
Have you eaten?
Does your daily routine
seem somehow empty?
Perhaps even ludicrous?
Yes!
You are experiencing
shon-ha'lock.
The engulfment.
It is the most intense
and psychologically
perilous form of Eros.
I believe humans call it
"love at first sight."
But... we're talking
about a holodeck character.
Irrelevant.
The emotional complex
in which you are
trapped is the same
and so is the cure.
Logical deconstruction
followed by a regimen
of meditative suppression
as I shall demonstrate.
Uh, a little further
to the left.
No. That's too much.
KIM:
Neelix.
Have you seen Marayna?
Oh... perfect!
Welcome, gentlemen.
Just getting
things ready
for tonight's
little get-together.
I completely forgot,
the luau.
Polynesian-style.
I've done my research.
Uh, Lieutenant Tuvok,
you neglected to R.S.V.P.
That was not an oversight,
I assure you.
Where is Marayna?
Who?
She's part of
this program.
Doesn't ring a bell.
How could you miss her?
She's tall, athletic, blond.
Oh, one of the
entertainment directors.
I believe she's giving Kes
a hydro-sail lesson.
Uh, no, no, not there.
There.
Harry. Tuvok.
The lake is perfect today.
Hello, Harry.
Hi, Marayna.
We were just talking about you.
You were?
Marayna said what
an excellent student you were.
She's a great instructor.
Ready to get
your ears wet?
Vulcans do not hydro-sail.
Oh, why not?
Lieutenant Tuvok
prefers the solitude
of his own quarters
and a game of kal-toh.
I'm sure we can do
better than that.
I'm going back
on duty. Thanks.
You're welcome.
There's a volleyball game
starting down on the sand.
Mr. Kim and I
would prefer some conversation.
Would you care to join us?
All right.
I tried a reverse
curl this morning.
I think
I pulled a tendon.
Feel that.
It's like a knot.
I'm sure it is.
Are you two friends?
Yes.
No.
We're colleagues.
I respect Mr. Kim
for his intelligence
and his integrity
and I assume he holds me
in the same regard.
So Vulcans don't hydro-sail,
and they don't have friends?
We have fellowships
and associations,
but without
the emotional dimension
humans experience.
Hmm. You and I are friends,
aren't we?
Um... y-yeah.
Good.
Chakotay to Tuvok and Kim.
Report to the bridge.
Acknowledged.
We're on our way.
There's a luau tonight.
You're coming, aren't you?
Both of you?
No.
Yes.
You've got to stop doing that.
Ensign.
As I predicted,
your responses were as formulaic
as a mathematical equation.
What do you mean?
Consider the expression
on your face
when Neelix did not recall
Marayna--annoyance.
That's not true.
It is quite true.
At that moment,
Neelix was functioning
in Vulcan terms,
as the soo-lak--
The third party, who by
his very lack of interest
trivializes your own.
I guess it did bother me.
And the arrival of Kes
with Marayna
then precipitated
in you the k'oh-nar--
The feeling of being
completely exposed.
I was embarrassed.
I was sure Kes
would take one look at my face
and know exactly what
I was feeling.
And when Marayna placed your
hand on her stressed tendon...
Let's not even talk
about that.
Bridge.
It's all so...
predictable.
That's just what
I've been trying
to get you to perceive.
To the trained
Vulcan intellect
intense romantic love
is nothing more
than a set of
stereotypical behaviors.
Not having our discipline,
typically, humans are
swept along by the process
until it ends.
How does it end?
Either in conversion
to a more balanced
stable relationship
or in tragic circumstances.
I can't have a balanced,
stable relationship
with a holodeck character.
Marayna's a computer program.
She could never feel for me
what I feel for her.
Exactly. Logic dictates
a single course
of action-- retreat.
To tell you the truth...
I don't even like
hydro-sailing.
The temperature's
5,000 degrees kelvin
and rising.
Captain?
We've located
a plasma strand
that looks like
it's seconds from igniting.
There is some kind of
unknown process
that's been keeping
this nebula
from going up like a torch.
We're going to see it in action.
And if there isn't?
I've got my hand
on the controls.
We'll be out of here before it
even touches our shields.
Captain, the temperature
is 9,000 degrees kelvin.
I'm picking up
a subatomic cascade reaction.
There she goes.
The plasma strand completely
burned itself out.
Without causing a chain reaction
in the nebula.
Harry, what put out
the flames?
Sensors show some kind
of dampening effect
between the strands,
but I can't isolate it.
Like a firebreak
in space.
If we understood
how this happened
we might be able
to find a new way
to contain
a warp core breach.
Or any plasma reaction.
It's an investigation
worth pursuing.
Tom, it seems safe enough.
Take us in for
short-range sensor scans.
Let's find out all we can
about this phenomenon.
Aye, captain.
I'll see all of you
at Mr. Neelix's luau.
I'm sure everyone
will be attending.
Lieutenant,
you look absolutely...
Tropical?
More along the lines
of "smashing."
Thanks.
Of course, nothing can quite
measure up with this shirt.
This is
an exact recreation
of a 1962 big daddy-o
surf special.
An American classic.
I'd say you put
just a little bit too much
thought into that.
Now that's where
you're wrong.
Let's go. I told Vorik we'd pick
him up at 1600 hours.
And you know
how Vulcan he gets
when anybody is late.
Vorik? I thought
we were meeting Harry.
Oh, he's not coming.
Why not?
He said he was busy.
With what?
I don't know.
Harry and I will meet
you and Vorik at the luau.
You're pretty confident about
your powers of persuasion.
Yes, I am.
( chiming )
Come in.
Surf's up, Mr. Kim.
Hi, Tom.
Harry, this is a luau.
You look like you're
dressed for a funeral.
What are you doing?
Vulcan meditation.
What for?
To suppress my emotions.
( scoffs )
Is something wrong?
Not really.
The... resort woman?
What was her name?
Marayna.
How did you know that?
For two days now every time
I look for you
it's always,
"he's in holodeck one."
And since you don't like
hydro-sailing
I figured something
was going on.
Am I that predictable?
You sound like Tuvok.
Tuvok? He told you
to do all this?
Logically, the best
course is retreat.
Meditation helps.
Retreat.
A classic case of Vulcan denial
if you ask me.
Come on, Harry.
We've all fallen
for a holodeck character.
It happens.
You deal with it
by staying with
your normal routine,
not by hiding out
in your quarters.
I'm not hiding out.
I'm deconstructing
the emotional complex.
Okay.
Have fun.
No, wait.
Computer, standard illumination.
I'm getting tired
of this anyway.
Computer,
one Hawaiian shirt...
COMPUTER:
Specify parameters.
Pineapple motif.
Greetings, Mr. Vulcan.
No, thank you.
I've done a great deal
of ethnographic research
on the Polynesian
cultures of earth.
The flowered garland--
Or lei--
is said to represent
the flowering of love.
It's a marvelous tradition,
don't you think?
Marvelous.
Oh... Oh, my.
Did I program
a centerpiece that big?
Computer, open parameter
adjustment file.
The life of
a recreational hologram--
Dining, dancing,
nonrestrictive clothing...
I see the allure.
Your turn.
Hmm.
Oh, thank you.
Tuvok...
I'm glad
to see you here.
I would never
disobey an order, captain,
no matter how burdensome.
There's a difference between
an order and a suggestion.
The evening's young,
lieutenant. Let's mingle.
Vulcans do not...
Curious.
CHAKOTAY:
What's that?
If you will excuse me.
A common error
among novice players.
By placing the t'an
on opposite sides
of the kal-toh
you are attempting to introduce
a spatial balance.
A strategy that will
most certainly fail.
Why?
Kal-toh is not
about striving for balance.
It is about finding
the seeds of order
even in the midst
of profound chaos.
May I?
Please.
How beautiful.
Kal-toh is not
about beauty.
I understand,
but it's still beautiful.
Did you learn
to play on Vulcan?
Yes. From the age of 5
I took lessons
from a master.
I thought you might enjoy
having an opponent.
Playing alone must get
a little predictable sometimes.
You are perceptive.
Yes, I am. Extremely so.
Aloha, miss.
Thank you.
Sir?
No, thank you.
You're the only one here
not wearing a garland.
Given the decor
it seems
somehow excessive.
I don't believe you.
I beg your pardon.
I think you're trying
to isolate yourself
and make a public protest
at the same time.
Explain.
You didn't want to be here
in the first place.
Being the only one without a lei
sets you apart
from the others,
allowing you
to symbolically maintain
your solitude.
And since everybody can see
that you're
the only one without a lei,
you're letting them know
that you'd rather
be somewhere else.
Your logic is impeccable.
Thanks.
Mmm.
I am starving.
Oh, me too.
Let's find us a spot.
This place
is filling up fast.
I have already
taken the liberty
of reserving a table,
lieutenant,
with a view
of the lakeside.
You did express
a fondness
for that
particular vista.
I did?
Five days ago in a conversation
we had in engineering
regarding
holodeck programs.
I guess maybe I did.
Good memory.
Of course.
Well then, ensign...
let's go.
Harry.
What?
Do you want to get
something to eat, or not?
I... I don't know.
Maybe this
isn't a good idea.
Listen, I'm going
back to my quarters.
Harry...
Tom...
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
I like the excitement
of the water.
The danger...
being tossed around...
by the wind and the waves.
But at the same time
feeling like
I'm in control.
The illusion of control.
That's exactly right.
Because no one
can control
the wind or the waves.
But for a few moments
when you're on the water
and the ride is perfect,
the feeling is that you can.
Do you ever feel that?
No.
Never?
Don't you have
an imagination?
If, by imagination
you mean the ability
to spontaneously
generate images within my mind,
then, yes, I have
a highly developed imagination,
as do all of my race.
All right,
imagine this--
that you, with your logic
and your reason
are skimming atop
endless waves of emotion.
You believe
you're in control,
but you know the control
is an illusion.
You believe that
you understand
the depths
beneath you...
but that, too,
is an illusion.
I can see why ensign Kim
finds you compelling.
I can see why
Harry admires...
and respects you.
Because it's obvious
that he does.
And... so do I.
I must return
to my quarters.
Please stay.
I've never met
anyone like you.
I must admit
I share that conclusion.
You are
a unique individual.
Then stay.
It is late.
I must go.
Then come back
tomorrow.
I'm sure the weather
will hold.
No doubt.
Please.
Perhaps.
Good night... Tuvok.
Good night, Marayna.
Computer,
end resort program.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
supplemental:
we've completed sensor scans
and confirmed our discovery
of an unusual dampening field
responsible for keeping
this unstable nebula
from going up in flames.
The field's origin
is still a mystery.
The dampening field
only seems to appear
when one of
the plasma strands ignites,
as if the fire itself
initiates the field.
Which puts out the fire.
A feedback loop.
One that's preserved this nebula
for hundreds of years.
Mr. Kim, do we have enough data
on this dampening field
to produce a field artificially
using the deflector dish?
Harry, do we have the data?
Yes, captain,
but it'll take a while.
We'll have to simulate
the process in the computer
and then try to re-create it
with the deflector dish.
Probably a few weeks.
The project
is yours, ensign.
Tom, resume course for
the Alpha Quadrant. Warp six.
Aye, captain.
Captain, propulsion
is not responding.
Bridge to engineering.
B'Elanna, what's going on?
I'm not sure, captain.
We're trying to track
the problem now.
Acknowledged.
Harry, give B'Elanna a hand.
The nebula
could be having an effect
on the ship's systems.
That's a possibility
we can't discount.
The warp drive is functioning
within established
tolerance levels.
Matter/anti-matter containment
is at recommended
field strength.
The impulse engines
are also...
Within tolerance.
Yes.
Most likely, there's
some kind of failure
in the computer
pathways.
Nothing's wrong
with propulsion,
but the commands
from the helm
just aren't
getting there.
The warp drive seems okay.
Impulse too.
I think the problem
must be somewhere else.
I think maybe...
the helm's being blocked.
Like... some kind of failure
in the computer pathways?
Maybe.
I just said all that.
You're not listening, Harry.
I'll return
to my station, lieutenant.
I'm sorry. I guess I've got
a lot on my mind.
Forget about her.
What did Tom say to you?
Not a single word.
I saw the way
you were looking at Marayna
yesterday.
Hi. My name's Harry
"read-me-like-a-book" Kim.
It's not that bad.
Apparently, it is.
I can't get her off my mind.
COMPUTER:
Input algorithm not accepted.
Why don't you
take a break?
I can handle it
from here.
Thanks. I'll be
in my quarters if you need me.
Deck three.
Computer, belay that order.
Holodeck one.
Computer, activate
Neelix resort program.
COMPUTER:
That program
is currently running.
Hello, Harry.
Enjoying yourselves?
Now I know why
you told me
to keep off
the holodeck.
Mr. Kim, you are misconstruing
the nature of this situation.
Your jealousy
is entirely insupportable.
Stop analyzing me.
I respected you,
I trusted you,
and you did this
right behind my back.
I have done
nothing of the sort.
Then what
do you call this?
A game of kal-toh,
which I am playing
with a nonsentient
computer subroutine.
Harry, I didn't intend
to harm you,
and I didn't do
anything wrong.
I'll accept that from her,
Tuvok, but not from you.
You said to stay away from her.
You should have done the same.
You're implying
a desire on my part
that simply
does not exist.
Marayna is an intriguing
interactive hologram.
Nothing more.
If you say so, lieutenant.
Mr. Kim, I value our
working relationship.
I would not allow a holodeck
character to disrupt that.
I think it's a little late--
Tuvok, Harry, please,
stop arguing.
Computer, delete the Marayna
subroutine.
Tuvok,
what are you...?
That's not going to help.
I never should have come
to you in the first place.
I should have
worked it out myself.
Let's try it again,
Mr. Paris. Warp six.
Course laid in.
Engage.
It would appear to me that
we're not moving, Mr. Paris.
I don't understand it,
captain.
Any ideas, B'Elanna?
Warp drive
is still on-line
and helm control
appears to be working,
but the engines
aren't responding.
It's possible we've got
a computer malfunction,
but I can't seem to localize it.
Let's run a level-four
computer diagnostic,
all systems.
Aye, captain.
Captain, I just got
aft thrusters to respond.
It's not much.
I'll take it, B'Elanna.
Tom, let's go.
At this speed,
we'll be completely clear
of the nebula by tomorrow.
Good enough.
Your move.
I think you'll find
my game has improved.
How did you get here?
Simple. I transferred myself
from the holodeck
to the sick bay,
then used your physician's
mobile emitter.
I deleted you from the holodeck.
But you only did that
for Harry's benefit.
I know you wanted
to keep seeing me.
I like Harry, but, uh...
well, you're different.
You're not like anyone else.
Why have you come here...
to my quarters?
You're like a new world
to me, Tuvok.
I want to know
everything about you.
I didn't realize how lonely
my existence was,
and I can't go back
to the way things were,
not without you.
Tuvok to Bridge.
Intruder alert.
Security team
to my quarters.
( alarm blares )
No!
Why did you do that?
Don't you want us
to be together?
Given your actions I have
no choice but to consider you
a potential threat
to myself and to Voyager.
But you're wrong.
I would never do
anything to harm you.
Make it stop!
( alarm stops )
You have access to the ship's
control systems?
And I'll use them all
if I have to.
You can't just delete me.
Where is this individual now?
When security got
to Tuvok's quarters
she downloaded herself
back into the computer
and onto the holodeck.
More to the point,
what is she?
Most likely a sentient
computer program.
I checked
the Starfleet database.
This kind of thing
has happened before.
The Enterprise-D
under Picard
was once taken over
by a holo-character.
We studied that case
at the Academy.
It gained control of the ship
from inside the holodeck.
Marayna may well
have done the same.
She was able to silence
the intruder alert
by an apparent act of will.
Does she have the run of
our entire computer system?
She may.
Is it possible that
she is the source
of our mysterious
malfunctions?
It's certainly possible.
If Marayna's able to manipulate
the ship's computer pathways,
she could have
disrupted propulsion,
and then covered her tracks
so we couldn't trace the cause.
But why?
What's her motivation?
I believe it has something to do
with her feelings toward me.
In my quarters, she made
reference to her loneliness
and expressed her desire
to continue our relationship.
But what does that
have to do
with knocking propulsion
off-line?
Could she be trying
to keep us near the nebula?
This all started
the day we got here.
That's when I first met her.
Maybe the nebula is somehow
affecting the holodeck.
Giving rise to an intelligence
that doesn't belong there.
It's possible.
In any case...
I can't allow her to gain any
further control over my ship.
Tuvok, Paris, Torres,
get down to holodeck one.
I want this situation resolved
one way or another.
She's locked us
out of the program.
We'll be lucky if we
can open the doors.
We're lucky.
Marayna may have
opened the doors.
Caution is advised.
I'll try to access
the inside control panel.
It's kind of creepy.
Marayna's attempting
to re-create the setting
of my previous
encounter with her.
You really know how
to pick them, Tuvok.
I got access
to the holodeck computer.
PARIS:
I'm not reading anything
unusual on the holodeck.
It seems to be
working perfectly.
There's a subspace signal coming
from outside of Voyager.
It's some kind of an uplink.
There's somebody on a ship
out there tapping into the--
( gasping )
B'Elanna!
( grunts )
( gasping )
( grunting )
Shoot the control panel.
( coughing and gasping )
Shield status?
Still holding, captain,
but the inertial
dampeners are off-line.
Starboard shields
are down to 80 percent.
What happened
down there?
Marayna attacked us
and attempted to restrain me.
She has control over
the holodeck characters.
But she's not actually
on the holodeck.
I found an uplink
and tracked it to the nebula.
She's on a hidden ship
or a space station.
She's manipulating the holodeck
from there.
She's been using the Marayna
character like a puppet.
As an interface.
A way to move around Voyager
to interact with us.
MARAYNA:
Tuvok, come back to me.
I'm waiting for you.
Harry, try to trace the uplink.
Find her.
Don't make this more difficult
than it already is, captain.
Are you responsible
for the plasma fires?
You're giving me
no other choice
but to force the issue.
What do you want?
Tuvok. I want Tuvok.
Let him come to the holodeck
alone,
or I'll destroy your ship.
Tuvok... you're back.
I had little choice.
We're alone now.
No one can see us
or hear us.
We can do whatever we want.
You don't have to pretend
anymore.
This is our world.
You've successfully
lured me here
by threatening the ship.
But any attempt to generate
intimacy between us
will not be successful.
I've isolated the source
of the uplink signal.
Standby to transport.
I understand
your sense of duty,
of loyalty
to your captain,
but we have
something stronger.
A connection that goes
beyond duty and loyalty.
I know you want
to be with me, Tuvok.
You must leave Voyager now
and allow us to continue
on our course.
I won't.
I suggest you reconsider
or Captain Janeway
will be forced to take action.
There's nothing she can do.
You're staying here
with me.
She'll just have to accept that.
Energize.
Transporting to the
source of the uplink.
Stop!
Shields are down to 47 percent.
Shields are gone.
Try to hail Tuvok.
I can't, captain.
Something's blocking the signal.
Marayna?
Your ship is helpless.
If I ignite one more strand
the hull will fail.
You are using the nebula
as a weapon.
My nebula.
I will fire if necessary.
You're too late.
I've already set
the ignition sequence.
Only I can stop it.
( tricorder beeping )
Are you alone here...
on this station...
in this nebula?
Yes.
It's my work.
I don't understand.
I keep the plasma fires
from chain reacting.
You are responsible
for the dampening field
we've been investigating.
That's correct.
I generate it from here
to preserve the nebula
so that others
from my home planet
may enjoy its beauty.
I watch the ships
when they pass by.
They don't even know I'm here.
You are... lonely.
By choice.
I prefer to be here... alone.
But you uplinked
with our holodeck
and created a character
in order to interact with us.
To amuse myself.
I've done it before.
Tapped into the computer
of a passing alien vessel,
examined all the little details
of their lives...
but I never expected
to find something
as... diverting
as your holodeck.
I never expected
to find you.
You...
are like nothing else
I've ever encountered...
and I can't be without you.
Stay here with me
and I will let
your ship resume course.
If it is the only option
I would willingly sacrifice
myself to save my crewmates.
No! That's not enough.
You have to want to be with me.
If you truly understood
who and what I am,
you would know that I could
never return your affections.
( voice breaking ):
But... you are more like me
than you are like them.
I-I-I've seen the way
you isolate yourself.
Even in a crowd of people
you're alone.
We should be together.
I must admit...
I found our conversation
stimulating,
your insight and intelligence
fresh and unexpected.
In other circumstances,
I would be willing
to spend time in your company
to continue to share
knowledge and ideas,
but I have a home
and a spouse on Vulcan.
I have a mission
and colleagues who depend on me.
I do not have a complete
understanding of emotions,
but I believe
that if you truly care for me,
you will not pursue
this course of action.
( sighs softly )
( beeping )
You may go.
Your communicator
will function now.
Tuvok to Voyager.
Go ahead, Tuvok.
I am ready to return.
Stand by to beam me aboard.
( ship's systems powering up )
( sighs )
Captain, ship's systems
are coming back on-line.
Acknowledged, Tuvok.
Standing by.
Consider this:
your feelings toward me
may be evidence
of a deeper need...
a more...
profound loneliness
than you are willing
to admit.
Why don't you call
for a replacement.
Let another
occupy this task.
Attempt for a time
to live among your own kind.
Logically, that would be
the best thing to do.
Yes.
Perhaps I will.
Tuvok to Voyager.
Ready for transport.
But what about you, Tuvok?
Will you always be alone?
TUVOK:
Security chief's log,
stardate 50471.3.
The remaining damage to
the ship was easily repaired
and we soon left
Marayna's nebula behind.
Voyager is back on course
and I have resumed
my normal routine.
( sighs )
( door opens )
Mr. Kim.
Would you be interested
in learning to play kal-toh?
I thought kal-toh
was beyond human understanding.
Not entirely.
Ensign...
I failed to respect
the complexity of your emotions.
I apologize
for my lack of consideration.
( sighs )
Don't worry about it, Tuvok.
Apology accepted.
( turns game on )
Won't this take years to learn?
It will, indeed.
May I join you?
No.
But... thank you.
( chuckles )