JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50537.2.
Routine scans
of an uninhabited star system
have revealed the presence
of gallicite,
a very rare substance,
on the fourth planet.
If these readings are right,
we're looking at a yield
of nearly a kiloton.
That would be enough gallicite
to completely refit
the warp coils.
They sure could use it
with all the damage
they've taken
the past two years.
Is there anyone in the area
who might consider this
their property?
There are indications
that a colony once existed
on the planet's surface.
However, it appears
to be long abandoned.
All right,
let's stake a claim.
I'll leave this
in your hands, B'Elanna.
Use whatever resources
and personnel you need.
You might want to talk
to Mr. Neelix.
I believe he spent some time
working in a mining colony.
Aye, Captain.
TORRES:
These tunnels are
clearly artificial.
Someone else must've
been interested
in digging up
this gallicite.
That should make it easier
to access the deposits.
True, but we have
to be careful.
There's been a lot of
seismic activity down there.
Look, these tunnels
are completely collapsed.
We should bring Tom Paris
on the away team.
He's had quite a lot
of rock-climbing experience.
I have spent several summers
exploring the Osana caverns,
which involved
some quite treacherous climbing.
Great. You two can be
our safety experts.
Have we completed
our preparations
to your satisfaction?
We're done here, yes.
Let me take
this opportunity
to declare Koon-ut so'lik,
my desire to
become your mate.
What?
In human terms, I am...
proposing marriage.
Do you accept?
Uh, this is a-a little sudden...
isn't it?
Besides, I thought that
Vulcan marriages were arranged.
Don't you already have somebody
back home?
She has sufficient reason
to consider me lost,
and has most likely chosen
another mate.
It's appropriate for me
to do the same.
And you've chosen me.
I've come to greatly admire,
not only your impressive
technical skills,
but also your bravery
and sense of moral duty.
All excellent qualities
in a prospective mate.
But you're a Vulcan.
I am... half-Klingon.
I really can't imagine...
Perhaps we are not
an obvious match.
However our differences
would complement each other.
You've often expressed
frustration
with your Klingon temper.
My mental discipline
would help you control it.
Furthermore, I feel that--
Wait, please.
Please. Um...
I see that you've given this
a lot of, um, logical thought,
and, uh, I really am
very flattered...
but my answer is no.
I'm sorry.
B'Elanna...
you may wish to reconsider.
Your choices for a mate
are currently limited
to 73 male crew members
on this ship,
some of whom are
already unavailable.
I'll worry about my
choices myself, thank you.
I should also remind you
that many humanoid species
are unable to withstand
Klingon mating practices.
Okay, that's enough.
Whereas, my superior
Vulcan strength would make me
a very suitable partner.
( gasps )
( sighs )
Here are the results
of his cortical scan.
So, what's wrong with him?
In addition to
a dislocated jaw,
Ensign Vorik seems
to be suffering
from a neurochemical
imbalance.
Meaning... what?
I believe I should
discuss that
with the patient
privately.
You're going through
the Pon farr, aren't you?
That's an extremely...
personal question, Doctor.
Yes, I'm aware
that Vulcans prefer
to keep their mating practices
very much to themselves.
There's almost nothing
in the medical database
beyond a few observations
made by Starfleet doctors
over the years.
Your symptoms--
the chemical imbalance and
loss of emotional control--
are consistent
with those observations.
Have you been eating
and sleeping normally?
I knew there was
something wrong.
I was hoping it wasn't...
this.
I assume this is
your first Pon farr?
There's nothing to be
embarrassed about.
It's a normal
biological function.
I'll do what I can
to help you through it,
but I'll need
a little more information.
We do not discuss it.
I'm afraid you'll have to.
You have a severe imbalance
in your brain chemistry.
If it gets much worse, it could
become life-threatening.
Now I need to know how Vulcans
deal with this condition.
We...
go home.
Every seven years
of our adult life,
Vulcans experience
an instinctual...
irresistible urge to
return to the homeworld
and... take a mate.
But in your case,
being stranded
halfway across the galaxy,
that's impossible.
Yes.
So, then, logically,
you try to find a mate here.
I assume that explains
your behavior
toward Lieutenant Torres.
I have always had great
respect for B'Elanna.
I hope she isn't too...
upset with me.
With Lieutenant Torres,
"upset" is a relative term.
In any case, we're going
to have to try to find
another way to treat
your condition.
Let's start with
a micro-cellular scan.
No!
I don't want medical treatment.
I will resolve this myself.
How do you intend to do that?
There are certain
meditative techniques.
I will be fine
if simply left alone.
Please...
allow me to return
to my quarters.
Confine me there if you wish,
but allow me to resolve
my situation privately.
Until I have a better idea
of how to treat
your condition...
I'll release you
to your quarters.
You'll be under confinement
and wearing a cortical
monitor at all times.
Thank you.
I'm concerned about Ensign
Vorik's cortical readings.
One returns to normal levels.
Then another one spikes.
It's chaotic,
as if the brain's
regulatory system
had simply shut down.
I can't tell if he's
making any progress
with these meditations.
I thought you could suggest
other possible treatments.
I cannot.
Is that because you don't know
or because you don't
want to discuss it?
For both of those reasons,
there is little help
that I can offer.
It is inappropriate for me
to involve myself
in Ensign Vorik's
personal situation.
For such an intellectually
enlightened race,
Vulcans have a remarkably
Victorian attitude about sex.
That is a very human
judgment, Doctor.
Then here's a Vulcan one.
I fail to see the logic
in perpetuating ignorance
about a basic
biological function.
There is nothing logical
about the Pon farr.
It is a time when
instinct and emotion
dominate over reason.
It cannot be analyzed
by the rational mind
nor cured by
conventional medicine.
Anyone who has
experienced it
understands that it
must simply be followed
to its natural
resolution.
Which is what, exactly?
There are three options
that I am aware of:
taking a mate, which Ensign
Vorik has already attempted;
the ritual combat,
which does not apply
to his situation.
Combat?
An ancient tradition
of fighting for one's mate--
which, as I have said,
is not relevant here.
The third alternative
is the intensive meditation
he has chosen to try.
Isn't there anything we can do
to help him with that?
I believe that any interference
would be unwelcome
and counterproductive.
You must allow him to face
this challenge privately.
If he possesses
enough discipline
to reach a point
of psychological resolution,
then his chemical imbalance
should correct itself.
The Vulcan brain
never ceases to amaze me.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
You've been a great help.
Ah, you two are awfully prompt.
Impressed?
Oh, it'll take
a little more work
than that to impress me,
Lieutenant.
Yes, ma'am.
All right. Let me show you
our target area.
Shouldn't we wait
for Ensign Vorik?
He's not coming.
This seems to be the most
accessible vein of gallicite.
We'll beam to the surface, then
go down through this passageway
until it dead-ends
in this chamber.
Then we'll descend almost
50 meters, almost straight down.
Do you see any problem
with that, Tom?
Um... well, as long as
we go slow and easy,
we'll be fine.
Good. You're all set, Neelix?
I've got a laser drill,
sample cases,
geo-spectral analysis kit--
In other words, you're ready.
Let's go.
This way.
Look over here.
This must have been
the colony.
Not more than 50
or 60 years ago.
Hardly enough time
for these structures
to decay so badly.
They must have suffered
some kind of disaster.
Maybe an earthquake.
Well, we'll send down
an archaeological team later on.
Right now,
we've got our own work to do.
Are we in a rush?
I just don't see any
point in wasting time.
Unless, of course,
you want to stall,
to put off demonstrating
your climbing expertise.
Grab your gear
and try to keep up.
( grunts )
No matter how real
a holodeck program may seem,
it just doesn't get
your heart pumping
like a genuine
physical challenge.
It's exhilarating.
If you're looking
for exhilaration...
NEELIX:
It didn't look
quite so steep
on the sensor map,
did it?
We're prepared for this.
We can handle it.
Let's go.
All this Starfleet
technology
almost takes
the fun out of it.
If you mean the fun
of wondering
whether your anchor
will hold
while you're dangling
over a cliff,
I think I'll pass.
See you below.
TORRES:
You go first.
I'll follow you.
( grunts )
Watch your footing!
You're right.
My heart is pumping faster.
Wait till we climb back up
with a pack full of gallicite.
Oh, I'm just
getting warmed up.
( screaming )
No!
( grunting )
( coughing )
Are you hurt?
You, you almost
got us both killed!
I'm sorry.
I don't know what happened.
( yells )
PARIS:
Careful, careful.
You might have broken it.
You had no business
rigging safety equipment
when you had no idea
what you were doing!
Calm down.
This wasn't Neelix's fault.
I saw him drive the piton,
and it was solid.
It must have malfunctioned.
You are hurt.
I'm fine.
No thanks to you two.
I would have been better
coming down here alone.
Don't you think you're
overreacting a little bit?
Just drag him to the ship. I'll
get the gallicite myself.
We can't leave you
down here alone.
PARIS:
He's right.
Let's contact the ship.
You get your hands
off of me.
( growls )
( yells )
B'Elanna!
What is wrong with you?
Nothing.
I'm in charge of this mission.
I'll finish it.
Wait.
NEELIX:
Go ahead, Tom.
I'll be all right here.
The last thing we need
is for all three of us
to split up.
Paris to Voyager.
We've got problems down here.
I haven't been able
to contact her.
She's either
out of communications range
or just not responding.
Where is she now?
The last location I can verify
is about ten meters below us.
I tried to stop her
from leaving, Captain,
but she got very hostile
and... bit me.
She bit you?
And she seemed
to be enjoying it
in a Klingon kind of way.
She's really not herself.
Any luck in getting
a transporter lock on them?
No. They're too far
beneath the surface.
Tom, I'm sending an away team
down to you.
We'll get Neelix out of there,
then go after B'Elanna.
Tuvok,
you're with Chakotay.
Captain, I'd like to request
a short delay.
I may have an explanation
for Lieutenant Torres' behavior.
( door chimes )
Go away.
I said... go away!
I'm sorry, sir.
No. I must apologize
for the intrusion,
particularly at this time.
Then you know.
Yes. I regret
that I must ask you some
uncomfortable questions
regarding
Lieutenant Torres.
Yes, sir.
It is important for me
to know specifically
what happened between
the two of you.
Was there any
physical contact?
Yes.
Please describe your actions.
It's... hard to remember.
I was acting irrationally.
I believe... I approached her.
I...
I touched her face.
I meant
to be gentle,
but she tried to move away
and then I was
holding her more tightly,
both hands on her face,
like this.
It felt very important
not to let go.
I'm... I'm not certain why.
I believe you were initiating
a telepathic mating bond.
I... didn't know
it could happen that way.
I wanted to bond with her.
That much I remember clearly.
Apparently, you succeeded.
Lieutenant Torres has been
displaying unusual behavior,
very much like
the early stages of Pon farr.
How is that possible?
She's not Vulcan.
There have
been instances
of Vulcans mating
with members of other races.
But she rejected me,
forcefully.
Even a brief moment of bonding
may have been enough
to disrupt her self-control,
as the Pon farr does in us.
In a half-Klingon, the effects
may be even more extreme.
I have to go to her.
You cannot.
Lieutenant Torres
is out of contact on the planet.
Then I'll find her.
B'Elanna needs me,
and I need her.
It is a far more
sensible strategy
to get her safely
back to Voyager,
and then decide on
the proper resolution.
The resolution must be
that we become mates.
It is only logical.
Lieutenant Torres has never been
a great follower of logic.
You think she'll
reject me again?
It might be wise
to continue your
meditative efforts.
I'll do my best, sir.
It is difficult to estimate
how soon her condition
will become life-threatening.
Life-threatening?
She could die from this?
Yes.
And you've
gone through it
every seven years
of your adult life?
You only need
to be concerned
with Lieutenant Torres'
situation.
Right.
Well, it looks like
finding her won't be easy.
Scanning range is limited
to about 20 meters,
and even that's
not too reliable.
You said she was
going after the gallicite,
so we'll do the same,
and hope it leads us to her.
NEELIX:
I'm ready to go, Commander.
Let's go.
( grunts )
( yells )
( grunting )
( clattering )
B'Elanna.
Tom.
Come here, you've
got to see this.
TUVOK:
How are you feeling,
Lieutenant?
Fine. This is
an active power system.
It must have been built
by the colonists.
We'll send somebody down here
to study it more closely.
Right now, we've got to get you
back to the ship.
No. No. This is my discovery.
It's my mission.
You don't understand.
This is the source
of the gallicite readings.
These conduits are covered
with gallicite plating.
It's exactly what we need,
and I found it.
Yes, Lieutenant.
You've succeeded
in your mission.
Now you must tend to yourself.
You're experiencing
a condition known as Pon farr.
Pon what?
Your emotional balance
has been disrupted.
You may not be in control of
your more aggressive instincts.
I lost my temper for a minute.
That's all.
Why are you all
staring at me like that?
TUVOK:
Please, come back
with us to the ship.
Just leave me alone.
Who are you? What do you want?
My name is Chakotay.
I assure you we have
no hostile intent.
She does.
B'Elanna, please.
She is suffering
from a chemical imbalance
which is affecting her behavior.
An imbalance?
Is it contagious?
No. However, she does
need our assistance.
We'd be glad to take her
and leave your territory.
Not before you tell me
why you came here.
We only came to find
some gallicite.
We thought this planet
was uninhabited.
Then why are you
carrying weapons?
It's standard procedure
for any mission
into unfamiliar territory.
Let me see one.
And what is that?
Some sort
of scanning device?
Yes. It's called
a tricorder.
But it didn't detect
any life-forms here?
No, it didn't.
( beeping )
What's that?
Seismic alert.
That wall is unstable.
Be careful.
( rumbling )
Watch out.
( grunts )
B'Elanna, don't!
PARIS:
B'Elanna!
There must be
a hidden door,
some kind
of a passageway.
I'm not picking up anything
like that...
or any life signs.
Then you're
using it wrong.
Yeah, that must be it...
or else these aliens
are generating
some kind of interference
so we can't detect them.
We have to get out of here
before they come back.
We can't leave
Chakotay and Tuvok.
If you have any ideas how
to find them, I'm listening.
( panting )
We have to get
back to the ship
and get some help...
for them and for you.
Why does everybody
keep saying
there's something wrong
with me?
I'll try to explain it to you,
but we've got to get moving.
There. Your serotonin levels
are stabilized for the moment,
but I'm concerned
about these fluctuations.
It's becoming more difficult
to compensate.
I will increase
my efforts...
to control them, Doctor.
I'd like you to consider
an alternative treatment
I've been developing.
No, I will deal
with this myself.
Ensign, your
life is at risk.
You don't understand.
How well a Vulcan copes
with this experience is
a test of his character.
I've already humiliated
myself and Lieutenant Tuvok
by allowing a private matter
to become so...
public.
Give yourself
a little credit.
You're doing
the best you can
under unusually
difficult circumstances.
If you were back on Vulcan,
you'd have your family and
friends there to help you.
I shouldn't need any help.
I know that
self-sufficiency
is very important
to a Vulcan,
but there is nothing
shameful in getting
a little guidance
every once in a while.
I'd like you to consider
my alternative,
and then you can decide
whether or not to try it.
DOCTOR:
Ensign.
I don't understand
the purpose of coming here.
Trust me. Ensign Vorik,
I'd like you to meet T'Pera.
Surely you're
not suggesting
that she become my mate.
Well, I wouldn't recommend
a lifetime commitment, but...
she might be
able to help you
with your
immediate problem.
She's a hologram.
She isn't real.
Then I assume you have
the same low regard for me.
You're a skilled
physician, Doctor,
but let me point out
the limitations
to your own experience
with physical matters.
I believe
we're discussing
your sexual difficulties
at the moment, Ensign.
And this
holographic mate
is the best solution
I can think of.
She won't be the same
as a real mate.
The difference is
all in your mind,
which, if I've understood you
and Mr. Tuvok correctly,
is where the Pon farr
must ultimately be resolved.
Let your mind
convince your body that she...
is exactly what you
need her to be.
Think of this as an advanced
self-healing technique.
It will still require
considerable
mental discipline
on your part.
There is a certain logic
to your suggestion, Doctor.
I will try.
Good.
Well, then, I'll leave
the two of you alone.
Tuvok must be wrong
about this Pon farr business.
It doesn't make any sense.
It does explain how
you've been acting.
I don't see
what's so strange.
How about
starting a fight
with a group
of armed aliens?
Shouting at Neelix?
Giving me this?
If I remember
my Klingon customs,
biting someone
on the face means...
I know what it means.
( angry grunt )
( panting )
All right.
So, maybe I do feel...
something, some kind of...
instinct.
What am I supposed
to do about it?
When we get back to the ship,
the Doctor should
be able to help.
Or there's always Vorik.
I am not helping
that Vulcan pahtk.
The idea of bonding
with him...
it's ludicrous.
What's this?
The tremor must have
shaken the rocks loose.
Well, they're in the way.
No, hold it.
We don't know how
stable this tunnel is.
An energy blast
might bring the rest of it
down on our heads.
Let go!
No.
I think I should
keep this.
Never pick a fight
with a Klingon, Tom.
I'm not going to fight
with you, B'Elanna.
Afraid I'll break your arm?
You should be.
B'Elanna, stop it!
This isn't about the gun.
This is about sex.
But that's not going
to happen right now.
I think it is.
See, I've picked up
your scent, Tom.
I've tasted your blood.
No.
No. I'm your friend,
and I have to
watch out for you
when your judgment's
been impaired.
If you let these instincts
take over now,
you'll hate yourself and me too
for taking advantage of you.
I won't do that.
( panting )
Maybe...
maybe we should
continue separately.
No.
You don't know how strong...
how hard it is to fight this...
urge.
Are you telling me
that I'm impossible to resist?
I wouldn't go that far.
Good.
Come on.
I want to know about the vessel
which brought you here.
Your propulsion systems,
weapons, sensors,
everything.
( instrument beeping )
You have an artificial implant
in your arm.
Yes. It was necessary
to replace the elbow joint
after I was injured
in a combat simulation.
I also want to know
about your medical technology.
Scientific advances,
artificial
intelligence...
I'd be glad to tell you
all about my people
and learn about yours.
There's no need
to hold us
here for interrogation.
You should expect
no better treatment
after invading Sakari territory.
As I said, we didn't know
there was anyone down here.
Yes... so you've said.
TUVOK:
Your people have
clearly made
every effort to avoid
detection by outsiders.
Is it so difficult
to believe
that those measures were
effective in our case?
If they had been fully
effective, you wouldn't
have found anything interesting
enough to bring you here.
That's something
we can help you with.
What?
We can show you
how we detected the gallicite,
so you can disguise it better.
We can also help you eliminate
the last traces
of the ruins on the surface,
so no one else
will be curious about them.
You've seen the ruins?
Yes.
I assume the Sakari
once lived there.
Long ago...
before I was born.
What happened?
My people never even knew
who the invaders were
or why they attacked.
It was all over
in less than an hour.
Some of the colonists
were fortunate enough
to escape into the mines.
We've lived here ever
since, where it's safe.
If the invaders ever learned
of our existence here,
they might return.
I can certainly understand
your caution,
but let us demonstrate
our good faith
by helping you
protect yourselves.
Then we'll go
and never bother you again.
Agreed.
But you will be supervised
at all times.
( beeping )
( deep rumbling )
( both panting )
We're almost to
the next passageway.
Can you make it?
Not much choice.
( both grunting )
( both coughing )
It's all right.
We'll find a way out.
We should use that weapon. It's
worth the risk now.
Well, I might agree with you
if I still had it.
It's buried somewhere
under all that.
What?!
Sorry.
( gasping )
Try to stay calm.
I know it's hard.
You don't know anything!
I feel like I'm crawling
out of my skin!
I need to do something.
I can't take this!
( panting and gasping)
( laughing )
You've never been hard
to get, Tom.
Well, I'm making
an exception.
I can't let
you do this.
Oh?
Oh, but you wish you could.
All those invitations
to dinner...
and on the holodeck,
the way you would stare at me
when you thought
I wasn't looking...
and get jealous
when I'm with someone else.
You can't tell me you're
not interested in me.
You're right.
I can't.
Then don't push me away.
Oh, believe me, I'd like to,
but I know
this isn't really you.
You've made it clear
that you're not interested,
and I have to accept
that's how you feel, even now.
No...
no, it isn't.
I was... I was just
afraid to admit it.
You see, I've wanted this
for so long.
Just let it happen.
I hope someday you'll say
that to me and mean it.
You'd let me go insane
rather than help me?!
You know that's not true.
You just...
stay away from me!
( insects buzzing,
birds chirping )
You called, Ensign?
Is there a... problem?
Not at all.
You seem...
much improved.
Yes.
Your holodeck therapy
was very effective.
I must compliment you
on an innovative solution.
I'm pleased to hear that.
This could be a
viable alternative
for space-faring Vulcans.
When we get back, I'm sure
Starfleet medical will...
never hear about your
personal experiences from me.
Thank you, Doctor.
May I return to duty?
Soon enough, Ensign.
I'll need to run
a few more cortical scans.
Mr. Vorik's biochemical
readings are stabilizing.
They're not back
to normal yet,
but I believe he's gotten
through the worst of it.
I'm ready to release him
from Sick Bay.
Good work, Doctor. Will this
treatment help B'Elanna as well?
I don't see why not.
As soon as the away
team gets back,
I'll send her to you.
I'll get to work designing
the half-Klingon
version of the program.
There's a copious
amount of information
in the cultural database
about their mating practices.
Did you know
that fracturing a clavicle
on the wedding night
is actually
considered a blessing
on the marriage?
As a matter of fact, I didn't.
I'm planning to do
a comparative study
of all these mating rituals.
It really is fascinating...
from a sociobiological
point of view.
I'm sure B'Elanna will
appreciate your efforts, Doctor.
( sighing )
TORRES:
Mm.
( moaning )
Where are we?
Still stuck in
the cave, I'm afraid.
The caves?
The gallicite.
Where's my tricorder?
No, we're not looking for
the gallicite anymore.
We're trying to get back
to the ship, remember?
No... I don't.
( clattering )
Are you two all right?
B'Elanna needs help.
We've got to get her
out of here.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Please respond.
Still nothing.
What's the matter?
Why aren't they answering?
There must be some kind
of communications problem.
I'm sure they'll
clear it up soon.
It may not be soon enough.
I am concerned about the rapid
progression of her symptoms.
You must help her now,
Mr. Paris.
If she does not resolve
the Pon farr,
she will die.
B'Elanna, I know this is
a pretty bizarre situation.
Probably not what either
one of us had in mind,
but it's too late
to worry about that now.
Tom...
What?
Be quiet.
So, this is the part
where you throw
heavy objects at me?
Maybe later.
I'm not sure exactly
what I'm supposed to do.
( throaty growl )
( throaty growl attempt )
( yells )
( grunting )
Well, what are you doing?
Enjoying myself?
Then show it.
( both grunting and panting )
You are my mate, not his!
What are you doing here?
I've come to claim you,
to fulfill our bond
and if necessary,
to face my rival!
Lieutenant Tuvok!
Ensign.
Sir, I declare
Koon-ut kal-if-fee.
The ritual challenge.
He intends to fight
to win his mate.
If you want a fight,
you've got one.
Hold on, Tom.
There's not going to be
any challenge.
Are you responsible for the ship
being out of contact?
It was necessary
to disable the communications,
transporters and shuttles.
No one will keep me
from my mate!
I am not your mate!
We will soon decide that!
If anyone is going to smash your
arrogant little face in, I will!
I take your challenge myself!
She has the right to choose
her own defender, even herself.
CHAKOTAY: Now just hold on.
Neither of you are
thinking straight right now.
They are following
their instincts
and I suggest
we allow them to do so.
You mean, let them fight?
It is logical.
Both must resolve their
Pon farr before it kills them.
We cannot wait
to hear from Voyager.
They'll tear each
other to pieces!
The risk of injury
seems preferable
to the certainty of dying
from a chemical imbalance.
Commander, I see no alternative
but to follow
Vulcan tradition.
All right.
Begin.
( yelling )
It's over, isn't it?
The blood fever
has been purged.
They will both recover.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50541.6.
We're following through
with Chakotay's offer
to help the Sakari
improve their camouflage,
and they've agreed to supply us
with a generous quantity
of gallicite.
Deck 2.
So looks like
you're feeling better.
Hmm.
You back on duty?
Yes.
Hmm.
Yes, I'm fine.
Thanks.
The refit
is going well.
We should have
new warp coils
by the end of the week.
Oh, good.
Glad to hear it.
Computer,
halt turbolift.
Look, this is ridiculous.
We are going to be together
on this ship for a long time.
You're right.
We have to pretend
that the whole mission
didn't happen.
But something did happen,
B'Elanna.
Look, Tom, I really
appreciate what you did--
what you were willing
to do for me--
but as far as I'm concerned,
I was under the influence
of some weird Vulcan
chemical imbalance,
and whatever I did,
whatever I said, it wasn't me.
Yeah, I know.
You're afraid that
your big, scary Klingon side
might have been showing.
Well, I saw it up close,
and, you know,
it wasn't so terrible.
In fact, I wouldn't mind
seeing it again someday.
Computer... resume.
Careful what you wish for,
Lieutenant.
Your call sounded urgent.
I think there's something
you should see, Captain.
We found this as we were
clearing away the ruins.
Undoubtedly, one of the invaders
who destroyed this colony.
JANEWAY:
The Borg.