CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 50614.2.
Ensign Kaplan and I
are returning to Voyager
after completing a scouting
mission in the Nekrit Expanse.
The nebula's
completely scrambling
our navigational readings.
I still can't get a fix
on our position.
Are you saying we're lost,
Ensign?
That... depends what you mean
by "lost," sir.
"Lost," as in you still
can't get a fix on our position.
I'm sorry, sir.
Try hailing
Voyager again.
No response. We must still
be out of com range.
Then we'll just
have to navigate
the old-fashioned way--
engage optical scanners.
Aye, sir.
I'm picking up
an asteroid field
at coordinates 113 mark 7.
Record it.
Uh, sir?
That asteroid field?
It's the same one
we passed two hours ago.
( sighs ):
Great.
We're not only lost,
we're flying in circles.
( console beeping )
It's a Federation
hailing beacon--
originating bearing
309 mark 4.
It's Voyager.
Well... at least someone
knows where we are.
Setting a course.
The signal's coming
from the planet's surface.
Is it possible Voyager's landed?
Sensor readings are sketchy.
I'm detecting
about 80,000 humanoid life signs
on the western continent,
some rudimentary structures
and technology,
but no energy signature
big enough to be a starship.
( console beeping )
I'm getting another hail.
The signal's very weak...
and it's definitely not
being sent by Voyager.
Try adjusting
the bandwidth.
FEMALE ( distorted):
...Colony to Federation vessel.
We need your help, urgently.
This is Commander Chakotay
of the Starship Voyager.
Please identify yourself.
( distorted ):
I'm not reading you.
Federation vessel,
please respond to this...
We lost them, sir.
They've identified us
as a Federation ship.
Who would know that?
Whoever they are, they're
asking for our help.
Launch a message buoy
letting Voyager know
we've landed in response
to a distress call.
( buoy whooshing )
This place looks like
a war zone.
I can't pinpoint the source
of the transmission.
Commander.
I'm Commander Chakotay
of the Starship Voyager.
We're responding
to a distress call.
We're looking
for whoever it was
that asked
for our help.
Commander!
( grunts )
( grunting )
( weapon powering up )
( gasping groan )
( both grunting )
Come on!
Take him inside.
( groaning quietly )
( groans )
FEMALE:
I'd lie still
if I were you.
You've got a nasty
head injury.
You're human.
My name's Riley Frazier.
What's yours, Commander?
Why did you attack us?
Those weren't my people.
I'm the one
who sent the distress call.
We rescued you.
What did you do with Kaplan?
Your Ensign.
She didn't make it.
I'm sorry.
I've got to get
back to my shuttle.
Your shuttle isn't there
anymore.
The people who attacked you
have already pulled it apart.
Relax, Commander.
I'm here to help you.
How did...?
How did I get here?
I could ask you
the same question.
I was pretty surprised
when I picked up
a Federation ship out there--
not that I wasn't happy
about it.
It's a long story.
Why don't you go first?
Seven or eight years ago...
I was working
as a Science Officer
on a vessel
in the Bolian sector.
We were attacked without warning
by aliens.
They overpowered us in minutes,
and those of us who survived
were put in some kind
of stasis.
The next thing we knew,
we were here on this planet.
It didn't take too many hours
of stargazing
to realize we weren't in
the Alpha Quadrant any longer.
There are other humans here?
Three that I know
of besides me,
what was left of my crew,
along with some Klingons,
Cardassians, Romulans,
and dozens of other species
I'd never seen before.
And the ones
that put you in stasis?
I don't know.
They must have had some kind
of colony here at some time
because of the ruined buildings
and equipment
they left scattered around.
We've never seen them again.
Everyone here has pretty much
the same story.
They were just grabbed from
wherever they happened to be
and dumped.
Why did those people
kill Kaplan?
We were no threat to them.
There are dozens of different
races on this planet,
all of whom were brought here
against their will.
Many of them are suspicious
of other species.
It's not exactly
a United Federation
around here,
if you know what I mean.
So those kind of attacks--
they go on all the time.
Resources are pretty limited.
It didn't take long
for the fighting to start.
First, a group of Klingons
attacked the Cardassians.
Then the Farn raided the Parein;
eventually things
just got out of hand,
and now it's anarchy.
But some of us,
a few hundred or so,
we've tried to make
the best of it.
We've established
a cooperative--
sharing work and whatever
provisions we have.
I've got to contact my ship.
The raiders
destroyed
the communications
array.
It'll take days
to fix it.
I can help you.
( grunts )
Our medic
examined you.
You suffered serious
neural trauma.
You're staying put.
And that's an order, Commander.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50622.4.
While Commander Chakotay
scouts for a faster route
through the Nekrit Expanse,
we are continuing
our month-long journey
through the sparsely
populated region.
You know, they
ought to rename
this place the
"negative expanse."
We haven't run across
anything interesting
for days.
If you're bored, Mr. Paris,
I'm sure I can find
something else for you to do.
The warp plasma
filters are due
for a thorough cleaning.
Now that you mention it,
Captain,
I find this region of space
a real navigational challenge.
( console beeping )
I believe I may have found
something else
to pique
Mr. Paris's interest, Captain.
It's an unidentified ship
on long-range sensors.
What sort of ship?
Sensor readings
are very limited,
but the vessel
appears to be stopped
directly in our current
flight path.
Harry, send
a standard greeting.
Aye, Captain.
( console beeping )
They're not
responding.
Try retransmitting the hail
on wide-band subspace.
Still no response.
We are entering visual range.
On screen.
KIM:
The Borg.
Red Alert.
All stop. Shields to maximum.
Stand by all weapons.
Tuvok, are they scanning us?
Curious.
None of the Borg systems
appears to be operational.
KIM:
He's right.
They're adrift.
Maybe they're trying to lull us
into a false sense of security.
That would not be consistent
with typical Borg tactics.
I want to try
a multiphasic scan.
Tom, stand by to get us
out of here in case they react.
Aye, Captain.
Proceed, Mr. Kim.
I'm not picking up any
active energy signatures.
And no life signs.
Well, that's a relief.
Perhaps. However,
we should avoid complacency.
The Borg are known to retrieve
their damaged technology.
It is quite possible
we will encounter
additional Borg vessels
which are fully manned
and powered.
That's exactly why we're
going to board that ship.
Captain?
This is a rare opportunity
to learn as much as we can
about Borg technology.
I might be able to get one of
their data nodes running
and find out
what disabled their ship.
If we're lucky,
we may find a weakness
we can use against them,
in case we run into
one of their
fully manned
and powered ships.
Tuvok, assemble
an away team. Tom...
Yes, Captain.
Take us
into transporter range.
We grow all our own food
in a cooperative garden.
It's delicious.
Sorry there's no meat.
No problem.
I'm a vegetarian.
Really?
I have recurring dreams
about my mother's
famous Texas barbecue.
So, your journey home--
how much longer do you
expect it'll take you?
About 67 years,
provided we don't find
a wormhole
or some other faster way
of getting back.
Haven't you
ever thought about
finding some nice
M-Class planet
and putting down roots?
We'd be missing
an incredible opportunity
to explore unknown space.
Besides, we've made a good life
for ourselves on Voyager.
I'm sure Captain Janeway
would be amenable
to take as many of your people
with us as we can accommodate.
Take us with you?
I assumed that's why
you sent the distress call.
You misunderstood.
We want to stay.
But you were brought here
against your will.
You just said
how dangerous it is.
For better or worse,
this place has become our home.
The people
in the cooperative...
they're like my ancestors--
Texas homesteaders.
I can understand
that, but...
We have a deep connection
to one another
that I've never felt before,
not even with members
of my own family.
I guess it's because of what
we've all gone through together.
What about those unfriendly
neighbors of yours?
We've been able to bring
a few of them into our group.
But you're right,
they're a problem.
( groaning quietly )
That's why we
want your help.
Security upgrades,
medical supplies,
maybe some weapons.
We're creating
a society here--
one that's based on tolerance,
shared responsibility,
and mutual respect
that people like you and I
were raised to believe in.
We're not about to give it up
just because it's difficult.
I'd better get back to work
on the communications array.
I'll come with you.
No!
You're still in no shape
to fight, if we're attacked.
I'll be back
to check on you soon.
( console beeping )
( hatch clanks and slides open)
( hatch slides closed )
TORRES:
It's like a ghost ship.
TUVOK:
Allowing yourself
to become apprehensive
can only be counterproductive,
Lieutenant.
I'm not being
apprehensive, Tuvok.
I'm just nervous as hell.
( tricorder beeping )
( beeping louder )
This is one
of the access nodes.
If we can get it
operational,
I should be able to tap into
the main data systems.
Tuvok...
there should be a compatible
micro-power conduit
somewhere in that module.
Connect it to this generator.
Lieutenant.
( tricorder beeping )
It's dead.
TUVOK:
As far as we can tell,
all activity on the Borg ship
ceased abruptly five years ago.
Our scans have detected
1,100 corpses.
TUVOK:
We located a breached
section of the vessel
where the spatial
vacuum preserved
several of the bodies perfectly.
We brought one aboard.
We're hoping
that an autopsy
might give us some clue
as to what killed them.
The question is,
why have the Borg
left one of their ships
and all its technology adrift
in space for anyone to find?
It is possible that
the deactivation of the ship
and its systems
severed the link
with the rest of the collective.
But what caused the shutdown
in the first place?
It could've been some kind of
natural disaster...
or...
Or what?
Maybe the Borg
were defeated by an enemy
even more powerful
than they were.
Tuvok, continue scanning
for any Borg vessels
in the vicinity,
as well as any other ships
that might be more powerful.
B'Elanna, you
and the Doctor
get started
on that autopsy.
In the meantime,
I think it would be a good idea
to rendezvous
with Commander Chakotay
a little ahead of schedule,
and let him know we've
run into some old friends.
( groans quietly )
( beeping )
Hello? Anybody there?
Riley?
( beeping )
( hatch clanks and slides )
( clanking and whirring )
( indistinct conversation )
( clanking and whirring
continues )
( instrument whirring )
( clattering )
Riley?
( gasps )
What are you?
Are you Borg?
We were Borg.
You mean you weren't
just kidnapped,
you were assimilated
by the collective.
At Wolf 359.
I was a Science Officer
aboard the Roosevelt.
But five years ago,
our cube was damaged by
an electrokinetic storm.
The next thing we knew,
our link to the
collective was severed.
We were free.
We could think
for ourselves again,
remember our names,
where we'd come from.
It was like waking up
from a long nightmare.
We took what we
thought we could use,
and transported
ourselves here.
Everything was new again--
the sounds of our own voices,
forgotten memories,
the taste of food.
Our original skin pigmentation
began to come back.
Many of us were able to remove
our Borg appendages.
I was even lucky enough to get
a prosthetic arm Orum created,
using Borg replication
equipment.
In spite of how
little we had,
it was a joyous, hopeful time.
And then?
After the euphoria wore off,
people started looking around,
and found they were living
among other cultures
they didn't understand--
or worse, species
they'd been taught to hate.
They turned against one another.
Things became chaotic.
The fighting, the raids...
But we're not all like that.
Everything I told you about
forming a cooperative,
building a new society--
I meant it.
Riley's telling the truth,
Commander Chakotay.
Look at me-- I was Romulan.
I was taught to hate
humans, the Federation--
but Riley and I
are friends now.
I'm part of
the cooperative.
Orum's our medic.
He's the one who examined you.
Why didn't you tell me
all this in the first place?
I know how people feel
about the Borg,
and they're right.
We did terrible things.
You'd been assimilated.
You weren't in control
of your actions.
Then you'll still help us?
I think, right now,
it's Commander Chakotay
who needs our help.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've detected a message buoy
launched
from Chakotay's shuttle
and are heading toward it.
The autopsy of the Borg corpse
is underway.
I must say, there's nothing
like the vacuum of space
for preserving
a handsome corpse.
Hmm...
Subject's abdominal organs
are unremarkable.
Pulmonary system
exhibits evidence
of extensive alveolar damage,
as well as a slight swelling
consistent with
exposure to space.
Ah...
In addition, there are signs
of severe
cardiac depolarization.
Sounds like
he was electrocuted.
Very good, Kes.
That would support our theory
about what happened
aboard their ship.
We think that their main power
conduits were overloaded
by a massive
electro-mechanical discharge.
Hmm...
this is intriguing.
What do you think that is?
It may be some sort of
axonal amplifier.
Kes, hand me
a cortical probe.
( whirring )
( shouts )
Shut it down!
( whirring stops )
What the hell happened?
Is it still alive?
Of course not. Apparently
I inadvertently activated
a backup neuroelectric
power cell.
The response
was purely autonomic.
There's no reason for concern.
I wouldn't be so sure
about that.
What do you mean?
That "autonomic response"
caused this drone
to reset back to its
original programming.
If the rest of those corpses
somehow reactivate--
we'd have a major problem
on our hands.
I'm afraid he's
getting worse.
There must be something
we can do for him.
You know better
than anyone
how limited our
medical resources are.
As far as I'm concerned,
there is only one option.
Would it be safe?
Would... what be safe?
As I'm sure you're aware,
the Borg
collective consciousness
is extremely powerful.
It allowed us to transfer
information instantaneously--
to think with one mind.
But what you may not
be aware of
is the link also has
inherent medical applications.
M-m-medical applications?
We were connected
by a continuous
neuroelectric field
that was capable
of regenerating
the damaged components
of an injured Borg.
Think of it as
a subspace transfusion.
Only instead of one
person giving blood,
there are hundreds,
perhaps thousands,
of donors
simultaneously transmitting
neuroelectric energy
to whoever needed it.
This process
was often successful
in healing both organic
and inorganic body parts.
This is all... very fascinating,
but I don't see how it helps me.
We still have Borg
neural processors implanted
in our nervous systems.
Removing them
would've killed us.
I see.
Using a portable
neuro-transponder,
we have the ability
to relink our brain patterns.
I thought you said
the link was severed.
It was.
But we can reinitiate it
among a small group,
for a short time.
We could generate
a neuroelectric field
that could heal your injuries.
You want to... hook up my mind
to some... Borg collective?
No, no, that's not it at all.
We'd be in complete control.
You'd simply be linked,
for a limited period of time,
to Riley, me, and a few
of the others in our group
willing to help you.
I'm not letting anyone implant
some neural processor
in my brain.
That wouldn't be necessary.
I'd simply attach
a small neuro-transceiver
to the base of your skull.
We'd initiate the link,
and the transceiver
could be removed as soon
as the procedure was over.
I assure you, other than
repairing neural tissue,
there would be
no lasting effects.
Thanks...
but I don't think so.
I-I can see
why you're skeptical.
I would be, too.
Look around you--
Orum and I, the others--
we're individuals.
We have distinct personalities.
We're not about to turn you
into some kind
of automaton.
I'll take my chances
and wait for Voyager.
I'm afraid that help
may come too late, Commander.
If we don't do something
to slow the neural degradation
immediately...
you will die.
Chakotay...
you have to make
a decision.
Any sign of Voyager?
No.
I can't change
who we are.
I wasn't truthful with you
before, and I'm sorry,
but please believe me
when I tell you
we only want to help you.
Orum will take
every precaution.
Please?
At least let us
try and save you.
It's either that or the happy
hunting grounds, huh?
Okay, then?
( deep electronic hum )
This is the
neuro-transceiver.
( electronic whirring )
RILEY:
Don't be afraid, Chakotay.
We're here to help you.
ALL:
Open your mind to our thoughts,
and concentrate
on getting well.
Hear our voices.
Open your mind to our thoughts.
Our collective strength
can heal you.
You're safe with us.
Feel the connection.
We're with you.
See who we are.
Know us.
You're not alone.
Our strength is your strength.
We can overcome your pain.
We welcome you
into our thoughts.
There's nothing to fear.
We won't let you die.
We're all one circle--
no beginning, no end.
( girl giggling )
GIRL:
Grandpa!
( girl laughing,
birds chirping )
How do you feel?
Don't worry.
It's gone.
It looks like the
treatment worked.
Orum says the
degraded tissue
has shown marked
improvement.
( groaning )
It was incredible.
I know.
I heard all of you--
your thoughts
inside my head--
as if they were
my thoughts.
And I could see myself...
through your eyes.
Then you must have
caught me staring.
I saw...
faces... planets.
What were they?
Images from the minds of
the people who linked with you.
Members of their families,
their homes...
I know things
about all of them...
about you.
You like bluebonnets.
My favorite flower.
You used to pick them
back home in Texas
with a man who carried
a walking stick.
My grandfather.
I know so much about you.
We shared a very
rare experience.
I felt that.
What about this?
It's a residual effect
from the link.
How long will it last?
An hour.
Maybe two.
Long enough.
Can you still hear
what I'm thinking?
Yes.
Then you know I want to be
closer to you.
I want us to know
everything about each other.
I want you to feel
everything I feel.
According to the buoy,
Commander Chakotay
and Ensign Kaplan
landed on the surface
in response
to a distress call
three days ago.
Can you locate
the shuttle?
( console beeping )
There is no sign of it
anywhere on the planet.
What about their combadges?
I'm only picking
up one signal.
It's in a heavily
populated region.
Signal's very weak.
Voyager to Commander Chakotay.
Do you read?
Ensign Kaplan,
this is Captain Janeway.
Come in.
Electrodynamic turbulence
from the nebula
is interfering with
the transmission.
It's going to take me
a while to clear it up.
CHAKOTAY:
Hand me that
hyper-spanner.
There.
That should at least
get the short-range
transmitters operational.
Now, if we can get
the signal amplifiers online.
I never would've
figured you
to be quite so handy
with a circuitry panel.
I guess you haven't learned
everything about me, have you?
Commander,
I just wanted to say
how grateful to you
we all are.
You're the ones
who saved my life.
But you've added so much
to the cooperative--
a renewed sense of hope,
an infusion of energy.
You have no idea
how invigorating it was
to have a new mind
in the link,
even if it was only
for a short time.
There have been so few of us
for so long, I...
Well, I'll let you two
get back to work.
I was so resistant
to being linked.
Now I'm almost sorry
it's over.
I know.
Last night, when we
were still connected,
I realized what it is
you really want from us.
It's more than just supplies
and security upgrades.
That's right.
It's a pretty
radical concept.
Sometimes radical problems
require radical solutions.
ORUM:
Riley!
Commander Chakotay!
We've detected a ship in orbit.
It must be Voyager.
I hope you'll at least
discuss our idea
with your Captain.
Why don't you tell her
about it yourself?
We've given it
a great deal of thought,
and we believe the solution
to our problem
is to reestablish
the neural link
among all the former Borg
living on the planet.
You can't be serious.
I know it sounds
extreme, Captain,
but I think you
should hear her out.
All right.
If you'll think about it,
Captain,
when we were linked,
we had no ethnic conflict.
There was no crime, no hunger,
no health problems.
We lived
as one harmonious family.
With all due respect,
Dr. Frazier,
you were "one harmonious family"
bent on the violent assimilation
of innocent cultures.
But we're not Borg anymore,
and we've learned from our past.
All we want to do
is to take the one good thing
that existed in the midst
of all that horror--
our unique ability to cooperate
and problem-solve--
and use it to create a safe
and productive community.
Tell me how, exactly.
The neuro-transponder
we've built
is only powerful enough
to link a small group of people,
like the one that helped heal
Chakotay's wounds.
In any case,
the effect is only temporary.
In order to reconnect the
entire population permanently,
we'd need
a much bigger
neuroelectric
field generator.
I'm afraid we don't have
anything like that.
But the Borg cube does.
What they're asking us to do
is reactivate that ship's
neuroelectric generator
and redirect it
toward the planet.
They want us to reactivate...
a Borg ship?
Not the whole ship,
just the generator.
And it only needs to be
operational for a few minutes,
in order to reactivate
the link.
There's no telling
what would happen
if we turned on one of those
generators, even for an instant.
For all we know, it would
attract other Borg vessels.
Captain, I can assure you,
we'd take every precaution.
Dr. Frazier,
I admire your tenacity.
I respect your courage.
I'll give you medical supplies.
I'll assist you
with upgrading your security.
I'll even take some
of you with us,
if you want to come.
But as to what you're proposing,
I have to tell you,
I'm extremely skeptical.
In fairness, however,
I will give it
some further thought.
Thank you.
What do you think?
If you're asking me
whether or not she's sincere,
I have to say yes.
You got to know them very well?
That's an understatement.
I heard their thoughts,
felt their feelings,
saw through their eyes.
And, in all the time
you were linked,
you never sensed
anything negative--
no hidden agenda,
no destructive intent?
No.
Bottom line:
Do you think we should do
what they're asking?
I really care about
what happens to these people.
So, in my heart,
I'd like to do
everything we can to help them.
But, if I were sitting
in your chair,
I'd have to take other
considerations into account.
Not only would it mean
imposing a choice
on thousands of people who had
no voice in the decision,
but it would also be taking
a terrible risk.
Helping to create
a new collective?
Who knows what
the repercussions might be?
I'll let Riley know.
( laughing )
I'm afraid
her decision was final.
I wish it weren't,
but I expected as much.
What about the raiders?
How long do you think
you can hold out against them?
Well, we'll just have to do
the best we can.
Who knows? Maybe we'll find some
other way to get to the cube
and reinitiate the link.
Come with us.
Chakotay...
We could replicate
some Texas barbecue.
I'm sure it won't compare to
your mother's, but I think it--
Don't think it's not tempting,
but my place is here.
I know you understand.
I've never understood
anyone better in my life.
Well, we're finished
laying in the supplies.
Thank you, Neelix.
Uh, we'd better
get going.
You okay?
What you need
is a good thrashing
on the hoverball court
to take your mind
off things.
You're on.
Good. I'll reserve
some holodeck time
as soon as we're back.
COLLECTIVE VOICES:
Chakotay, can you hear us?
Did you say something?
No.
Are you getting
a com transmission?
No. Why?
Must've been my imagination.
You sure you're okay?
I'm fine.
Chakotay, we need your help.
Chakotay?
We need your help.
I'm going to tell the Doctor
he needs to take a look at you
as soon as we're back.
Torres to Sick Bay.
Don't do that.
Chakotay,
give me the phaser.
( groans )
Captain, Commander Chakotay's
shuttle has changed course.
Try hailing them.
( console beeping )
No response.
They are increasing speed
to maximum impulse.
Tom, lay in a pursuit course.
Tell Neelix we'll rendezvous
with his shuttle later.
COLLECTIVE VOICES:
Chakotay,
transport to module 47 omega.
The bunker is under attack.
47 omega.
Section nine, mark coordinates.
We are under attack.
Nine alpha alpha.
We must hurry.
The bunker is under attack.
47 omega.
Section 9.
Mark coordinates.
We are under attack.
( grunting with effort )
Proceed to interlink console
three beta six.
Hear our thoughts.
Our thoughts are one.
Interlink three beta six.
Proceed to interlink console
three beta six.
Hear our thoughts.
TUVOK:
Check that area out.
This way.
COLLECTIVE VOICES:
Lower right panel,
attach power conduit 166.
Hurry.
Pathway pi two.
We are under attack.
Activate
the neuroelectric generator.
Quickly.
Power circuit mechanism.
Activate the generator.
Help us. We must activate the
neuroelectric generator now.
Chakotay, need your help.
Losing time.
Commander, take your hand
away from that console,
or I will be forced to fire.
You must not let them stop you.
You must do this.
( grunts )
You must move power circuit
mechanism alpha
to position one.
( console beeping )
( powering up )
( deep humming )
Hear our voices. We welcome you
into our thoughts.
Feel the connection.
( rumbling )
( clicking and whirring )
Mr. Kim.
Voyager, emergency beam-out.
Chakotay, B'Elanna
and the away team are all back,
and we've tractored in
the shuttle.
Take us out of here slowly.
( console beeping )
Captain, the Borg ship
is powering weapons.
Mr. McKenzie, full power
to the shields.
Arm all phaser banks
and prepare to fire.
KIM:
Captain,
the Borg ship
has initiated
a self-destruct sequence.
It'll go in three seconds.
Get us out of here.
Report.
KIM:
Shields are holding.
No injuries or hull damage.
What the hell
happened back there?
KIM:
Audio transmission,
Captain.
From the planet's surface.
Let's hear it.
COLLECTIVE VOICES:
We are the new cooperative.
We have destroyed
the Borg cube.
We regret that we forced
Commander Chakotay
to assist us,
but it was necessary
for our survival.
His link with the cooperative
has now been severed.
Our lasting gratitude.
( transmission ends )
His neuropeptide levels
have returned to normal.
And there are no
residual traces of the link?
None.
How were they able
to reestablish the connection?
My best guess is that
the residual neuropeptides
heightened his
telepathic receptivity.
I thought their limited
equipment made it impossible
for them to form the link
over great distances.
Apparently, once
they repaired
their communications
array,
they were able to use it
to amplify the signal
from their neural
transponder.
Would you two
please excuse us?
I don't know what to say,
except... I'm sorry.
Based on what
the Doctor's told us,
it's clear you were acting
against your will.
Maybe so,
but somehow that doesn't
make me feel any better.
I helped them repair
their communications array,
and I told you
they were sincere.
Helping others, Chakotay--
that's part of who you are.
Given everything
you believe in,
I don't see how you could've
behaved differently.
But I couldn't have been more
wrong about them, could I?
I don't know.
I'm not saying I'm happy
about what happened.
But so far, they haven't
acted like typical Borg.
They saved us from that cube,
and they let you go.
But they didn't hesitate
to impose their
collective will on me
when it served
their interests, did they?
No, they didn't.
I wonder how long
their ideals will last
in the face of
that kind of power?