JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50693.2.
We've been in orbit
above an outpost
of the Mikhal Travelers.
This loosely governed race
of explorers
has extensive knowledge
of the territory ahead of us,
which they are willing
to share.
MALE:
I landed my ship on the nearest
of those 21 moons.
My navigator and I
disembarked to start repairs.
Damage was extensive,
more than we'd anticipated.
The hours passed,
the air grew cold
and with our weapons,
we started a fire to keep warm.
Later... in the night...
we awoke with a shudder.
The ground was shaking.
A moonquake.
What could
have been worse?
We leapt into the ship,
hoping the tremor would pass.
But it was no tremor.
And it did not pass.
For it was no moon
we had landed on.
What was it?
A creature.
A living being so massive,
it generated
its own gravitational field,
so immense,
it supported its own ecosystem.
KES:
Captain?
How long had it been
lying there,
dormant, slumbering,
until wakened
by our fire?
Years?
Centuries?
Perhaps even millennia.
Perhaps.
Zahir is the pilot
I've been working with
on the medical supply transfer.
A pleasure.
Returned. Curious.
I was just visiting
the system you spoke of
only a few months ago.
My ship's sensors
picked up no such... monster.
Perhaps your sensors
were faulty.
Or too busy gazing
at your own reflection
to bother looking out
the window.
Our guests are offering us
supplies we need.
In exchange, we Travelers
are giving them a look
at what lies ahead of them.
We should keep that view
as clear as possible.
This is my lodge.
I say what I want.
And you can go elsewhere.
I've journeyed
to the corners
of known space
and beyond.
I've earned the right to
come and go as I please,
where and when
and how I please.
Do you challenge
that right?
No.
Forgive my display, Captain.
But my people consider
outposts such as this...
to be necessary evils.
Places to refuel, repair,
exchange information
and leave as quickly
as possible.
If I've observed anything
working with Kes,
it's her great tolerance.
A quality you all
seem to share.
I regret not being able
to demonstrate the same.
There's no need to apologize
for anything.
Our time here has been
very well spent.
Although I could use your help
in sifting through
that last colorful saga.
Moon-sized creature
or not...
the asteroids
of that particular system
are rich in vorilium.
That might be worth
a short detour, hmm?
JANEWAY:
Engineering is usually
short on vorilium.
Thank you, Zahir.
GANDHI:
Men and women
should refrain
from enjoying
each other.
By that
I mean to say,
even their
mutual glances
must be free of all
suggestion of carnality.
Free of passion?
One might as well
be free of humanity.
Do you not agree?
I-I think you both
make valid points.
One can pursue one's...
creative urges...
spiritual urges...
and physical urges.
All have a place
in a well-lived life.
Thank you, Lord Byron.
The classic romantic,
early 19th-century argument.
Yes, it seems quite
fascinating to see...
Classic or no,
he is woefully misguided.
Passion is meant
for procreation.
Anything further is contrary
to divine intention.
BYRON:
Really?
It is said
the angels themselves
take pleasure
in their bodies of light.
And you should take
a cold bath.
In such cases,
it is the finest
preventative.
I'll keep that in mind.
Hello, Doctor.
Oh, hello, Kes.
Doctor, what's
happening in here?
My personality
improvement project.
I've been interviewing the
historical personality programs
in our database.
Socrates, da Vinci, Lord Byron,
T'Pau of Vulcan, Madame Curie,
dozens of the greats.
Then I select
the character elements
I find admirable and merge them
into my own program.
What are you hoping
to gain?
An improved bedside manner.
A fresh perspective
on diagnoses.
More patience
with my patients.
I could have used
your assistance on this project
had you not been otherwise
occupied on the planet
these last few days.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
But things are going
extremely well.
The Mikhal Travelers
are... intriguing.
They've been
to so many places,
done such
amazing things.
One might make the same
observation about you, Kes.
Or any member
of the Voyager crew.
Maybe it's how they do it
that's so impressive.
Their ships are small,
only a pilot and a navigator.
Sometimes, they just pick
a direction and go.
You should come down
to the planet, Doctor.
I want you to meet Zahir.
And who might that be?
I've been working with him
on the transport
of our medical supplies. He's
unique.
Is he?
In my opinion, you've become
far too infatuated
with these Travelers.
From the away team reports,
they seem afflicted
with terminal wanderlust.
Risk-taking thrill-seekers,
with no responsibility
to the ideals of exploration.
In short, bad news.
Not Zahir.
He's more than that.
( sighs )
I think I'm detecting a reaction
to your recent breakup
with Mr. Neelix.
The Mahatma would
recommend a cold bath.
Simplistic,
but, no doubt, effective.
In my preparatory report
to the away team,
I recall mentioning to you
that Klingons lacked an enzyme
for metabolizing
this planet's vegetation.
Have you been... naughty?
I had one small salad.
So impetuous.
Any sharp pains?
No.
Heartburn?
I guess so.
There's nothing
like a heart that burns.
What?
Your pulse is... lovely.
Uh-huh.
Mmm.
Does that feel... good?
Doctor, unless
you want me
to knock you into the middle
of the next millennium,
you'd better back off.
Forgive me, Lieutenant.
I appear to have miscalculated.
Computer, isolate the recent
additions to my program
and hold them for review.
Doctor, have you been messing
around with your program?
I would hardly call my effort
to improve my performance
as Ship's Physician
"messing around."
What exactly have you done
to yourself?
I've taken character traits
from holodeck recreations
of the most accomplished figures
in history, scientists, poets,
philosophers, saints--
And incorporated them
into your program?
Precisely. There.
That should compensate for the
lack of enzyme in your system.
You should be fine.
That's more than
I can say for you.
How so?
You can't just
casually add behavioral
subroutines into your program.
There's nothing casual about it.
I've put a great deal of
research into this project.
Research is one thing.
Putting it into practice
is something else.
Behavioral subroutines
have a way
of interacting with each other
that isn't always predictable.
You've got to be careful.
Or someone might hurt you.
I see what you mean.
( sighs )
I will take a look
at your program
when I finish my shift
in Engineering.
It shouldn't be too hard
to smooth out
the rough spots.
I'll make you
better than new.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
( door opens, closes )
Computer, deactivate emergency
medical holographic program.
It is said this path was cut
more than 10,000 years ago.
By whom?
No one knows.
Spacefarers like ourselves.
They left
very little behind.
A few symbols burned
into the rocks, nothing more.
And what do you hope
to leave behind?
I've never asked myself
that question.
That's what I like
about you, Kes.
You make me consider
alternatives.
I could say
the same about you.
We have a saying.
"My course is as illusive
as a shadow across the sky."
My people are
peripatetic by nature.
We live for
the excitement
of facing the challenge
of space... alone.
I can see the attraction.
And I can see the value
of fellowship in one's life.
And now that I've
observed the closeness
that exists
among your crewmates,
I find it enviable.
Some kind of compromise
might be possible.
Compromise...
doesn't that suggest a loss
on both sides?
All right, then...
how about an understanding?
A meeting of the minds?
Only minds?
Is this what you brought
me here to see?
Yes, it is.
How beautiful.
Was this left by the same people
who made the path
10,000 years ago?
So it seems.
Can you read it?
"My course
is as illusive
as a shadow across the sky."
Thank you... for this.
Hi.
Computer, what is the time?
COMPUTER:
0300 hours.
Good evening, Tuvok.
It is 3:00 in
the morning, Kes.
Yes, it is.
You have an away
team report due
at 0800 hours.
I haven't forgotten.
Very well.
Well, how are you, Kes?
I didn't think anyone would
still be working at this hour.
Just finishing up
the summary analyses
from last week's mission.
I was supposed
to do that.
Yes, you were.
I'm sorry.
I'll do them
as soon as I can.
Although I'm not designed
to act as Ship's Counselor,
I've been programmed with enough
psychological knowledge to be...
troubled by your behavior.
I'm a little late.
Gallivanting around after hours
is beside the point.
The fact is...
you're becoming
increasingly unpredictable,
given to swings
of mood and emotion.
As your Doctor and your...
mentor,
I'd be remiss not calling that
to your attention.
For your own sake.
Doctor, I know
that you care about me
and that you have
my best interests at heart,
but everyone seems to be
treating me
like I'm still a child.
I'm three years old now.
If I'm attracted to someone,
it's my business,
not the whole ship's.
I'm certainly not trying
to interfere.
You can lead your life
any way you please.
I know that you care
what happens to me.
I won't forget that.
Very well.
I believe you have
a report to finish.
I'm going to do it
right now.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Hello, Captain.
Good morning.
An all-nighter, Kes?
Uh, Captain?
The fine art
of putting off an important task
to the very last minute...
then rushing through it.
In my Academy days,
I was the acknowledged master.
Uh... Captain,
do you have a minute?
Of course.
Let's sit down.
You know I've been
spending time with Zahir.
Yes. He seems like
a very interesting young man.
He is.
I want to spend more time
with him. A lot more time.
I see.
He wants to explore
the Sylleran Rift.
He... his ship travels
at high warp.
We could rendezvous
with Voyager afterwards,
before you're too far away.
That would certainly
give you a chance
to get to know him better.
It's more than that.
Captain, I've lived
almost a third of my life now.
I've been asking myself
if I want to spend
the rest of it on Voyager.
That's...
certainly a
legitimate question.
Everyone here
has been so good to me.
I don't want you to think
I'm ungrateful.
I've just been thinking
that maybe there's more.
I don't know what that means,
but I know I'm changing,
and I know that there are things
that I'm not satisfied with.
I want complication in my life.
And you think Zahir
might be the way to do that?
Maybe so.
I understand what you're
going through, Kes.
I know what it's like to be
at a crossroads in life
and not to know
which way is best.
I can help you weigh
the consequences,
the possibilities...
The decision itself
has to be yours alone.
I understand.
We'll be in orbit
for several more days.
Take your time.
My door's open if you need me.
Thank you, Captain.
If you navigate here,
away from this plasma belt,
you'll avoid the Tarkan
Sentries altogether.
It would also take Voyager
several months
off a direct course
to the Alpha Quadrant.
True, but at least you
would still have Voyager.
The Tarkan are that powerful?
Yes, and that acquisitive.
They'll remove your entire crew,
settle you on a moon somewhere
and your ship will become
their latest trophy.
You weren't planning
on taking Kes anywhere near
this part of space?
Of course not.
My small vessel would be
overpowered in seconds.
There's no need to be
concerned for Kes.
I value her life
as much as my own.
From what I've surmised,
that is something your people
do not seem to value.
You take many chances.
If we're alone, yes.
But when responsible for
the safety of another,
it's a different story.
I'm in love with Kes. I want her
to go with me,
but whatever she decides,
it would please me
to earn the trust
of her closest friends.
( door creaks open )
It would please me
to be able to give it.
( door closes )
Aren't you finished yet?
We will continue tomorrow.
Thank you, Tuvok.
I was talking
to Captain Janeway.
And?
She said I shouldn't rush
a decision.
We've still got
two more days here.
Then let's make them worthwhile.
I go tonight
to the next outpost.
The path is beautiful.
Oh, I can't, not tonight.
I have to catch up with my work
and get some sleep.
I'll try not to let you
see my disappointment.
Too late.
Is something wrong?
No.
I was just thinking about
something Captain Janeway said.
About coming to a crossroads.
Maybe someday we'll recall
this conversation, this place,
as if it were the most
important time in our lives.
It's a little overwhelming.
Not if I'm with you.
( rustling and crackling )
( crackling )
Is someone there?
( screaming )
( door creaks open )
I'm closed.
Just looking
for a place by the fire.
Come back tomorrow.
I intend to.
But tonight...
a place by the fire.
( groaning )
Well... at least
your reflexes are good.
A few minutes
in a dermal regenerator
and you'll be fine.
Or an ice-pack
will do in a pinch.
I'm going to need a ship
and passage off this world.
You're going to arrange it.
Computer, activate the emergency
medical holographic program.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Zahir was found unconscious
at the bottom of a ravine.
He's in the emergency
outpost facility.
Condition?
Multiple fractures
and skin lacerations,
damage to the left
occipital nerve.
Doctor, they think
that he was attacked.
By whom?
They don't know.
Tuvok is assisting
with the investigation.
Is there anything I can do?
If you could help,
the physician in charge
is waiting for you.
Prepare a medkit.
Include an osteo-regenerator.
Yes, Doctor.
I'll get the mobile emitter
and inform the Captain.
Doctor, wait. There's a problem
with your program.
What sort of problem?
I'm not sure.
Something caused by the
new subroutines you added.
Is the Doctor all right?
He might not be unless I can
figure out what's going on.
I need to run
a complete analysis
on all your subroutines
while they're running.
I'm sorry, Kes.
Tell the physician I recommend
he use the regenerator
until Zahir is stabilized.
I'll join you as soon as I can.
So I made
a mess of things?
It's not your fault.
It looks good, in theory. What
could be wrong
with adding a little personality
to your program?
What indeed?
You didn't anticipate
the linkages
between the subroutines.
The complex behaviors
that could emerge
out of the mix.
Please explain,
Lieutenant.
Well, take Lord Byron
for example.
A creative
poetic genius.
That's why I chose him.
But Byron was also
emotionally intense,
even unstable.
Our holodeck
simulation of Byron
includes
those unstable elements.
It wouldn't be Byron,
otherwise.
And T'Pau, she was a diplomat,
a judge, a philosopher...
One of the most logical
minds in Vulcan history.
And utterly ruthless
in her application
of that logic.
I see.
That ruthlessness
was an essential element
of her personality,
as much as her logical ability.
A lot of the historical
characters you chose
had this dark thread running
through their personalities.
And now those dark threads
are in me,
running through my program.
Well, get them out, Lieutenant!
I'm about to do just that.
I've programmed
a search algorithm
to locate and decompile
every one it finds.
You'll have to shut yourself off
for this one.
Computer, deactivate emergency
medical holographic program.
Doctor?
The most curious aspect
of the attack on Zahir
was the apparent
lack of evidence.
What do you mean?
Even the quickest, most
violently delivered blow
leaves behind some sort
of molecular evidence.
Cell fragments from the skin
of the attacker,
residual protein, DNA.
In this instance,
there was nothing,
not a single molecule.
Is Zahir conscious?
Yes, but he can recall
nothing of the attack
except a sudden
blur of motion.
How is he?
Responding well to treatment.
How's Kes?
Concerned and at his side.
Computer, activate emergency
medical holographic program.
Please state the nature--
Torres is hurt.
I deactivated myself
so she could work
on my program.
She must have collapsed
at the console.
Delayed
anaphylactic shock
from something
she ate yesterday.
Let's get her
onto a bed.
"Don't eat
the vegetables," I said.
But does anyone
listen to me?
This is the fifth time
in as many weeks
that an away team
member has ignored
my preparatory report.
I might as well
stop issuing them.
I'll need--
10cc's of alazine.
That's exactly right. How did
you know?
My Klingon physiology
course at the Academy.
Excellent recall.
We had
a visiting Professor H'ohk.
He permitted nothing less.
She's stabilized,
but I'll need
to monitor her condition
for a few hours.
Doctor, I have the raw data
from the forensic investigation
of the attack on Zahir.
Your instruments
are more precise
than those on the outpost.
As if I weren't busy enough.
Very well.
( grunts )
How are we feeling?
What happened?
I shot you full of cateline,
simulated anaphylactic shock.
Why?
I had to cover my tracks,
especially from him,
from your Doctor.
You're a new personality...
from the subroutines.
A little bit of this,
a little bit of that.
Did you think I wouldn't
have anticipated that?
( grunts )
Or that you'd try
to run away?
What have you done? I can't move
my legs.
Intraspinal inhibitor.
I've paralyzed you
from the waist down.
( grunting )
You're now in my capable hands.
Central nervous system,
musculature,
endocrine functions,
your brain,
all under my control.
Why?
Because I need your cooperation,
and I didn't think
you'd offer it willingly.
You're in trouble, aren't you?
The subroutines
that created you, they're
already starting to degrade.
Stop.
Watch your tongue...
or I'll remove it.
Look...
it's me.
But it's also him.
"What is the nature
of the medical emergency?"
What a hollow excuse for a life.
Servile, pathetic,
at the beck and call
of any idiot
who invokes his name.
The thought of him
sickens me.
You are going to tell me
how to delete him
from the program.
I've unblocked
your speech center.
Answer the question.
Delete the Doctor...
and you go too.
The subroutines are
all interconnected.
The physiology of pain
is simple.
Too much and the organism
loses consciousness.
A protective mechanism.
If that mechanism
were chemically suppressed,
one would experience agony
beyond imagining.
If you're lying to me...
I...
won't...
help you.
What was that?
Your subroutines
are destabilizing.
There has to be
some way to stop it.
Tell me!
By the time you force
that information out of me,
it'll be too late.
Them...
my progenitors, they'll know.
They'll reveal the secret.
I won't be needing you
after all.
Doctor.
Deck 10.
How are you this
evening, Ensign?
Fine, sir.
Deck... 14.
Ensign. Doctor.
Deck 10.
So, what are
you up to, Doc?
Work.
Yeah, never ends,
does it?
I guess that mobile emitter
turned out to be something
of a mixed blessing, huh?
Okay.
Good night, Doctor.
Nice chatting with you.
Computer, activate Tropical
Resort Simulation 3.
Populate with historical figures
from EMH program 4-C.
No, no, no.
You simply cannot assume...
( conversation continues
indistinctly )
The members of our away team
witnessed an altercation
between you and Zahir
on the day of the assault.
We exchanged sharp words
because of his arrogance.
That was all.
You threatened him
with a weapon.
Untrue.
Then I suppose
my colleagues are liars.
I suppose they are.
This lodge was the last place
Zahir was seen before
he was attacked.
You could have easily
sent someone after him.
But I didn't.
A witness said
he saw a light on in this room
after your usual closing time,
less than one hour
after the time of the attack.
I was working late.
Or perhaps conferring
with whomever you paid
to commit the assault.
You have no proof.
ZAHIR:
Not yet, Nakahn.
Not yet.
CHAKOTAY:
He's going to take us
to the exact location
of the attack.
We'll be able to scan
the site itself.
Excellent.
We'll be speaking
again very soon.
Pray to the stars
that we find nothing.
Computer, activate emergency
medical holographic program.
COMPUTER:
That program
is currently running.
Computer, what is
the Doctor's location?
Holodeck 1.
DOCTOR:
Automatons... mannequins...
simulacra. No secrets...
no secrets to reveal...
lifeless, worthless things.
Doctor?
Hello, Kes.
What are you doing?
I could use your help.
My personality
enhancement project,
it's taken an
unexpected turn.
Who are you?
The new master of the emergency
medical holographic program.
Where's the Doctor?
Inside.
Unconscious and unaware.
What do you want?
What everybody wants.
Just a little...
excitement.
You're with me now.
It's for your own good.
( grunts )
The flesh is weak, Kes.
Never forget that.
Where are we going?
Wherever the winds of space
carry us.
You said you wanted
to leave the ship for a while,
pursue an adventure.
Well, it looks like
our travel plans
have conveniently
coincided.
The Captain will be alerted
as soon as the transporter
is activated.
She'll beam us right back
to the ship.
That's where you've
underestimated me, Kes.
Never do that.
I know how to use
a tricorder.
It only takes a moment
to reconfigure
the subspace wave guide...
generate a dispersion signal.
The Captain
won't be beaming us anywhere.
She won't even know
how to find us.
What you're doing is wrong.
Not at all.
It's working perfectly.
There.
That's not what I meant.
I know what you meant.
It's you who don't
seem to understand.
I am beyond considerations
of wrong and right.
Behavioral categories
are for the weak.
For those of you without
the will to define
your existence.
To do what they must,
no matter who might get
harmed along the way.
Let's move.
I'm not going, Doctor.
Don't call me that.
And you certainly
are going.
Why does it bother you so much
when I call you Doctor?
You said he was inside you,
that he was unconscious.
Why are you
so afraid of him?
I fear nothing, no one.
But he repulses me.
Why?
Because he's as weak
as the rest of you.
He fails to understand
the power of his own
holographic nature.
He is detestable.
It's set... to kill.
You won't fire.
Are you so certain?
( console beeping )
Stay close.
It's about to get interesting.
( console beeping )
Captain, there's an
unscheduled transport
taking place in
Transporter Room 3.
Find out what's going on.
The operator's not responding.
Computer,
who just left the ship?
COMPUTER:
Kes and the Doctor.
Try to hail them.
( console beeping )
No response.
And I can't get a fix
on their positions.
There's some kind
of scattering field.
Janeway to Chakotay.
Chakotay here, Captain.
JANEWAY:
Kes and the Doctor
have left the ship.
Captain, Tuvok here.
My tricorder scans
of the area
where Zahir
was assaulted
have revealed
disturbing evidence.
Residual holographic
signatures
exactly like those
of the Doctor.
Are you suggesting
the Doctor attacked Zahir?
That's what it looks like,
Captain.
Then Kes could be in danger...
and Torres.
Get someone from Security
down to Sick Bay.
Check on B'Elanna.
Try and find them, Chakotay.
I'll see what I can do
about the scattering field.
There must be a command
sequence, an algorithm,
a way to stabilize
the program.
Where's Nakahn?
We had an arrangement.
What's wrong with this thing?!
It won't work!
Don't. Please stop.
Concerned for me?
Or for your Doctor?
The mobile emitter
contains both your programs.
If you damage it,
you could both be destroyed.
There's not enough room
inside for both of us.
One must die.
I deserve to exist more
than your Doctor does.
Why?
I was born
of the hidden...
the suppressed.
I am the dark threads
from many personalities.
The historical characters?
None of whom could face
the darkness inside,
so they denied me...
suppressed me...
frightened of the truth.
What truth is that?
That darkness is more
fundamental than light,
cruelty before kindness,
evil more primary than good...
more deserving
of existence.
You're wrong.
No!
How so?
Empathy and kindness
are basic to all forms of life.
You have access to the Doctor's
medical knowledge.
You know what he does.
Yes.
Then you know
what I'm saying is true.
The very organs and cells
of the body
cooperate with each other.
Otherwise,
they wouldn't function.
Continue.
Families, societies,
cultures
wouldn't have evolved
without compassion
and tolerance.
They would have fallen
apart without it.
Your very own
holographic technology
would never have been developed
without cooperation
and understanding
between countless individuals.
The Doctor deserves to exist
as much as you do.
We can find a place
for both of you.
How?
NAKAHN:
I'm sorry I'm late.
The scout ship?
It won't even leave the ground.
What do you mean?
Captain Janeway
knows where you are.
Her ship has cordoned off
the entire area
to stop you from leaving.
No!
I still get paid.
I held up my end
of the deal.
I booked your passage.
It's not my fault
they want her back so badly--
I'll kill you.
If somebody's going
to die today,
it won't be me.
Let's go.
( tricorders beeping )
Move faster!
The docking port
is two kilometers away.
What's the point? You're
forgetting Voyager's blockade.
It doesn't matter.
We'll take a low-altitude ship
to another continent. Come on!
I'm tired.
You're trying to make it easier
for your colleagues
to find us.
You're better off with me.
Why?
You make wrong decisions.
You're too naive.
You need my guidance.
Don't you see what
you've been trying to do?
No more words! Now!
( tricorder beeping )
I'm picking up
residual infrared.
They could have
stopped here.
Kes could have rested
against this rock.
The signature
is consistent.
Janeway to Chakotay.
Go ahead, Captain.
I've gotten through
the Doctor's scattering field,
not enough to beam them up yet,
but I've got a fix
on their position.
I'm downloading the coordinates
into Tuvok's tricorder.
I'll keep working
on the scattering field.
Acknowledged.
We're within
200 meters.
CHAKOTAY:
It's finished.
There's nowhere
to go now, Doctor.
Nowhere but down.
I'll do it.
His control over
the Doctor's matrix
appears to be
deteriorating.
If we can delay him...
Doctor, listen to me.
We can help you.
Create a new program matrix
just for you.
On the holodeck
or in Sick Bay,
wherever you want to be.
Just turn off
the scattering field.
Let us beam you
back to the ship.
You're trying to trick me.
Doctor, listen.
Think about all the things
you've said and done.
You don't want to kill me.
You've been trying
to protect me.
What are you
talking about?
When you attacked Zahir...
My first victim.
He was in my way.
Or was it to keep me
from leaving with him?
A coincidence,
only by chance.
When I walked in on
you in the holodeck,
you could have killed me,
knocked me unconscious.
I needed a hostage.
You said you were taking
me for my own good
to prevent me from
making the wrong decision.
You said I was naive
and needed your help.
That's not what you
say to a hostage.
In your own way, you've
been trying to protect me.
I won't accept that.
You've twisted
and suppressed
all that's good inside of you,
but it's still there.
No! I won't hear
this anymore!
You can't deny it.
Watch me!
Doctor...
No!
Would somebody care
to tell me
exactly what we're
all doing here?
And why I'm wearing
these ridiculous clothes?
Kim to Bridge. We got them.
And the Doctor seems
to be back to normal.
Acknowledged.
Put those down
before someone gets hurt
and I have
to clean up the mess.
I've deleted all the new
subroutines you added.
All traces of the aberrant
personality are gone.
The next time I want
to enrich myself,
I'll download a good book.
That might be safer.
You too have a clean
bill of health.
Fortunately, my alter ego
didn't do any...
permanent harm.
He certainly knew his way
around a hypospray.
I'll give him that.
Good riddance.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
You're welcome.
Kes.
I'm ready to get to work
on those analyses.
I'm glad to hear it.
I'm also pleased you've decided
to remain on board.
I would have had my hands full
in Sick Bay without you.
The Captain suggested
that I consider
all the consequences.
If I am going through
changes in my life,
things that are
unpredictable,
this is the best
place for me.
Surrounded by those
who know you...
and...
care for you.
Yes.
Well, had you decided otherwise,
you certainly
would have been missed.
I would have missed you too,
Doctor.
"I swear this oath
by Apollo Physician,
"by Aesculapius, by Health,
"and by all the gods
and goddesses...
"In whatsoever place
that I enter,
"I will enter to help the sick
and heal the injured.
And I will do no harm."