Fire.
The asteroid is fragmenting,
but most of the debris
is still on a collision course
with the planet.
Target the fragments.
Destroy them.
That asteroid should have been
vaporized. What happened?
I'm not sure.
Sensors showed a simple
nickel-iron composition.
We shouldn't be
seeing fragments
more than a centimeter
in diameter.
Ambassador,
I'm afraid I was right.
This isn't
going to work.
The same thing happened
to us yesterday.
We tried to vaporize
two incoming asteroids,
but they fragmented
and struck the surface.
I've destroyed
most of the debris, Captain.
However, targeting scanners
were unable to track
two of the fragments.
They have already entered
the upper atmosphere.
The debris impacted
on the largest continent
approximately 500 kilometers
from the southern tip.
The central desert.
Fortunately that region
isn't heavily populated.
Substantial cratering,
atmospheric shock waves...
and large concentrations of dust
and other
stratospheric contaminants.
How long
until the next asteroid hits?
Approximately six hours.
Can you give us an idea
of its trajectory?
Same continent, but this time
on the eastern coastal region.
Our largest colonies are there.
Over 5,000 citizens.
Captain,
we appreciate your efforts,
but I think it's time
we considered an evacuation.
According to my analysis,
there are at least
12 more asteroids
heading in our direction.
How can we hope to destroy
them all even with your help?
Incoming hail from the surface.
It's coming from one
of the heavily damaged areas.
On screen.
Ambassador,
I've been analyzing the debris
and I've discovered
disturbing evidence
that the asteroids
are not what they seem.
They are composed
of artificial materials.
I must meet
with you immediately.
I think we can stop--
I've lost the
transmission.
Location?
I can't find them. Too much
interference.
That was Dr. Vatm,
our most prominent
astrophysicist.
He mentioned the composition
of the asteroids.
Could he have found
something important?
At this point,
Ambassador,
I don't know what that
discovery could be.
Mr. Paris, can we send a shuttle
down through that turbulence?
It would be a rough ride,
but I think it's possible.
Our chances of finding
Dr. Vatm are slim.
We should evacuate
the colonies.
We haven't time to evacuate
all those people.
I won't give up,
not now.
Captain, I'm asking
for your help again...
but I won't ask you
to risk your crew.
In for a penny,
in for a pound.
Excuse me?
It's a human expression,
Ambassador.
And it means
we're not leaving you now.
Tuvok, assemble rescue teams.
We'll send down three shuttles
to find Dr. Vatm.
Aye, Captain. Mr. Paris?
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Engineering.
B'Elanna, I want you
to beam aboard
a sample of the debris
from that last asteroid.
Let's find out why
it wasn't vaporized.
I'm going to study the data
we've collected so far.
I'll be in my ready room.
I need analeptic compounds.
Are you ill?
No, no! I'm feeling
quite vigorous.
I requested a place
on the rescue team
as part of
my Starfleet training
and the Captain said yes.
So, I thought
it might be useful
to bring along a few
extra medical supplies.
We have some analeptic compounds
in the bio lab.
I'll get them for you.
May I suggest
a tranquilizer?
No, no, no.
I'll be fine.
Just that I'm
a little apprehensive.
I've been assigned
to Lieutenant Tuvok's team,
and no matter what I do,
I can't seem to please him.
Vulcans are notoriously
difficult to impress.
Mr. Tuvok seldom
acknowledges my brilliance.
A word of advice,
Mr. Neelix.
Try to restrain
your... enthusiasm.
You're there to
observe and learn.
Yeah.
It's good advice,
Doctor.
Altitude:
15 kilometers.
Velocity: mach 2.1.
Entering the upper
troposphere.
( gasping and groaning )
Mr. Sklar, are you all right?
I'm an exo-geologist.
I prefer working on the ground.
We'll be landing shortly.
Try to relax.
Ah!
What's happening?!
We're entering a layer of
electrodynamic turbulence.
Full power
to thrusters.
Thrusters
aren't responding.
Attempting to level
our descent.
Oh, oh!
We're losing main power!
I will have to land
the shuttle manually.
Brace for impact.
Commander, I've lost contact
with Tuvok's shuttle.
Hail them.
No response.
Notify Lieutenant Paris
and the others.
We may have a team down.
Torres to Bridge.
Go ahead.
We've beamed aboard
a piece of the debris.
I'll be right there.
Ambassador?
( thumping )
( coughing )
TUVOK:
Dr. Vatm.
I heard what sounded
like a ship crashing.
I came looking for you.
This is Hanjuan.
He's a miner at the nearby
gallicite excavation.
He heard your
ship too.
Have you seen any other
vessels like ours?
No. Just you.
Doctor, you said
you had information
on the composition of
the asteroids. What is it?
That data is classified.
I can only speak
to the ambassador.
You may also speak to me.
Your ambassador sent us
to find you.
No.
I prefer to wait.
Doctor, we almost died
trying to get that information.
Tell us.
Be silent, Sklar!
Now, gentlemen, there's
no point in arguing.
Right now, we have to get
this shuttle off the ground.
Unfortunately, that will
not be possible.
All primary systems
are off-line.
Warp drive and impulse engines
have been destroyed.
I suggest we repair
the com system
and send
a distress call.
How long
will that take?
Several hours
at least.
We don't have several hours.
When the next asteroid hits,
it could destroy
this entire region.
We've got to
get out of here soon.
I assure you, we're doing
everything we can.
Mr. Neelix,
please go outside
and inspect
the toroidal antenna.
I need to know if any of
the signal relays were damaged.
If they were,
I can try to repair them.
A damage report
will be sufficient.
I've been studying
with Lieutenant Torres.
She gave me a full orientation
on shuttlecraft systems.
The damage report, Mr. Neelix.
Aye, sir.
In the meantime,
I suggest everyone
try to remain calm.
Allowing anxiety
to overcome you
will only hinder
the efficiency of our efforts.
He's really
a very pleasant fellow
once you get to know him.
And intelligent.
I'm sure he'll have the com
system up and running--
Neelix.
On my way.
( strong wind blowing )
Why won't you
share the data?
Excuse me.
Mr. Tuvok?
You couldn't have
finished already.
Not exactly.
What I mean to say is,
I know I'm here to observe
and I don't mean
to step out of line,
but I think I've observed
a way out of here.
Where?
I saw what appeared to be
an orbital tether
anchored nearby.
Yes, we use those
to lift cargo from the surface
to the orbital
supply stations.
May I assume it uses
magnetic leverage
to lift the carriage?
Yes.
What is your point?
What if we use that carriage
to climb the tether?
The tether's
over 300 kilometers long.
It takes 12 hours
to reach the station.
Well, we wouldn't have to go
all the way to the station.
We just have to leave
the ionosphere.
Once we get above
all this interference,
we can contact Voyager,
they'll beam us aboard.
VATM:
I've already considered
that option.
The carriage was damaged
on the last impact.
The induction coils
are off-line.
Maybe we can replace the coils
with attitude control thrusters
from the shuttle.
It would take
a little creative mechanics,
but I think we can do it.
I spent two years on a tether
maintenance team on Rinax.
The principles
are undoubtedly the same.
Our probability
of being detected
by Voyager
or the other rescue teams
is greatest
if we remain here.
SKLAR:
What if they don't
find us in time?
He's right. We should try
the tether.
It's better
than sitting here
waiting to be buried
in dust.
I've helped rebuild
a dozen mag-lev carriages.
Give me a chance
to get that one working.
If I can't, we'll come back
and wait for the others.
Very well.
You won't regret this,
Lieutenant.
We need to get
to the base of the tether.
( beeping )
I think we can
integrate our thrusters
into the induction matrix,
but we'll need to--
Looks like
somebody's been here recently.
Get away or
I'll kill him!
Drop your weapon!
Now!
This is my shelter.
These are my supplies!
We have no interest
in your supplies.
We are here to use the carriage
to get to safety.
He's telling the truth.
We'll take you with us.
The carriage is damaged.
Yes, we know.
The induction coils.
But we've brought equipment
to replace them.
I know it's been difficult.
This catastrophe has taken
it's toll on everyone.
But you have got to believe us.
We only want
to get off the surface.
What-- What about
the oxygen converters?
They've been damaged too.
They can't produce
enough air for six people.
Maybe we can augment
the converters.
We brought along
some equipment
that might do the trick.
I don't have enough
rations for everyone.
Don't expect me
to share.
If I can fix the tether,
no one will need your rations.
We have a starship in orbit.
They'll beam us aboard
once we leave the ionosphere.
If I'm not mistaken,
it sounds like you know a thing
or two about tethers, as well.
Not really.
I'm a foundry worker.
Good.
We could use someone
with metallurgical knowledge.
Let's get to work.
Have faith, Mr. Vulcan.
We'll be tether-borne
in no time.
( sighs )
I've completed
the mineralogical scans.
The rock is composed
of tryoxene, olivine...
Wait a minute.
I'm reading
a concentration of triadium.
Triadium?
Isn't that an alloy?
Yes.
B'Elanna, give me
a hand with this.
TORRES:
This doesn't look like any
asteroid I've ever seen.
But I'll bet it's the
source of our triadium.
It looks like a control node
for some kind
of guidance system.
Ambassador, I have a feeling
these asteroids aren't striking
your planet by chance.
Are we ready to bring
main power back on line?
I... I think so.
The coil bypass is active.
Bypass is holding.
Congratulations, Mr. Vulcan.
We've done it!
We must still repair
the oxygen regenerators
and the damaged
tether couplings.
Then let's get started.
I'll go check
on the oxygen supply.
How's it coming,
Lillias?
I still can't get
this power relay on line.
I'm not an orbital engineer.
I can't do this.
Maybe I can help.
Let's see.
Aha.
You need to recalibrate
the pressure valve...
like this.
That should about do it.
We're going
to need a name.
A name?
For the mag-lev carriage.
Whenever we finished
building a tether on Rinax,
we named the carriage
for good luck.
Any suggestions?
No.
How about...
Alixia?
"Alixia"?
My favorite sister.
She was always
taking me out to explore.
She showed me
the Caves of Touth...
the equatorial dust shrouds.
Once, she even took me
hunting for arctic spiders.
Whenever I think of her,
I think of adventure.
And this is an adventure
she would appreciate.
What do you think?
Where is your sister now?
She was killed
when I was a young man
in a war on my homeworld.
My entire family was lost.
I'm sorry.
I still see each of them.
Every night before I go to
sleep, I recall their faces
and share something about my day
with each of them.
Tonight, I'm going to have
quite a lot to tell them.
Thank you.
I have a sister too.
Halla.
Three weeks ago,
after the first impact,
our home was destroyed
and we were separated.
I haven't seen her since.
I don't even know
if she's alive.
When we get back to Voyager,
I'll ask my Captain
to help you find her.
TUVOK:
Mr. Neelix?
Excuse me.
Yes, sir!
Your interpersonal activities
are delaying our progress.
What do you mean?
Since we arrived,
you have spent as much time
engaged in idle conversation
as you have
making repairs.
I'm just trying to cheer
everyone up a little.
Your function at the moment
is to repair this vessel,
not to boost morale.
This is not the holodeck,
nor the Mess Hall.
This is a life-threatening
situation
and your attention
should be focused
on one thing alone,
our safe return to Voyager.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'll finish
as fast as I can.
LILLIAS:
Once we start
moving up the tether,
will we be able
to reverse course?
It will take several hours
to reach the station.
TUVOK:
We've only been able to fix
three of the seven power
supplies.
( Hanjuan grunting )
( equipment powering up )
TUVOK: ...were to turn back,
we might not be able
to break through the ionosphere.
Mr. Sklar,
examine this piece.
See if the...
NEELIX:
Dr. Vatm!
What are you doing?!
He's opening
the launch doors!
He's leaving without us!
Dr. Vatm!
( no audio )
Please stop!
The tether's base
hasn't been secured!
If he launches now,
he'll destabilize
the entire cavern!
Wait, please!
Don't leave us here!
Stand aside.
It's too late!
The cavern support structure
is collapsing.
We've got to
get out of here.
Can we launch?
I think so.
Seal that door.
I despise
enclosed spaces.
Hang on.
(metal clanking and rumbling)
NEELIX:
Velocity:
30 kilometers per hour.
Internal
atmospheric pressure:
700 millibars.
Altitude: 800 meters
and climbing.
We're losing mag-lev cohesion.
NEELIX:
All right. We have to
stabilize that right away.
Otherwise, we'll go
into free fall.
You mean, we're going to drop?
How do we prevent that?
Neelix!
Hold on! Hold on!
I'm thinking!
Velocity. Let's try
increasing the velocity.
It should stabilize
our ascent.
See if you can increase power
to the tether couplings.
( groaning )
Routing backup power
to the tether couplings.
Stand by. I'm going to try
giving her a little more speed.
Velocity:
47 kilometers per hour...
and holding.
Mag-lev cohesion...
stable.
We're all right.
Good girl, Alixia.
I knew you could do it.
"Alixia"?
I named the carriage
after my sister.
For good luck, no doubt.
We will need it.
One of the oxygen converters
has ruptured.
We'll have to find a way
of increasing output
to the other converter.
Otherwise, we'll run out of air
about halfway up.
What are the chances
of our reaching the ionosphere?
I'd say they, uh...
they were pretty good.
We did leave ahead of schedule,
and that could cause
a few glitches along the way.
Glitches?
I wasn't able
to get the auto-ascent sequencer
back on line.
That means, I'll have to keep
controlling the ascent manually.
And there is the problem
of maintaining atmospheric
pressure.
I'm already beginning to detect
a few fissures in the hull.
We must repair them.
Where is the emergency
containment grid?
Containment grid. Containment
grid.
Uh...
I'm... I'm not quite sure.
Mr. Neelix, you told
me you had experience
with this kind
of technology.
I did. I did.
Sort of.
They weren't exactly
what you might call
working carriages.
They were
more like prototypes.
Specifically.
All right, they were models,
one-tenth scale,
but they were
extremely detailed.
You built models.
Yes, but they were
basically identical
to real mag-lev carriages.
Same principles,
same mechanical components.
I was planning
to familiarize myself
with all the systems
on this carriage.
I just didn't plan
on leaving ahead of schedule.
But don't worry, I've got
everything under control.
There is little we can
do now that we are
30 kilometers
above the surface.
I suggest we continue to--
VATM: What are you doing?!
LILLIAS:
Let's go.
You wanted to leave?
Fine, then leave.
( beeping )
( grunts )
That is enough.
He may be crucial to
the survival of your colonies.
He would've let us
die down there.
That is no justification
for murder.
Dr. Vatm, why did you
try to launch without us?
Does it have to do with
the discovery you made
about the asteroids?
Answer him, or
I'll throw you out myself.
Compose yourself,
Mr. Hanjuan.
Once we return to Voyager,
we will find out...
Who put you in command?
This rescue mission
was authorized
by the Captain of my ship
and the ambassador
of your government.
I say we throw Vatm
out the door.
We could use
the extra oxygen.
If you are trying
to intimidate me,
I should inform you
that, as a Vulcan,
I possess physical strength
many times your--
( groans )
It is going to be
a long and perilous journey.
As such, I will need
your full cooperation.
Understood?
Yeah.
Mechanical glitches
would seem to be
the least of our problems.
PARIS:
We've just completed
our third low-altitude survey.
There's no sign of Dr. Vatm
or Tuvok and his rescue team.
We're monitoring a major
dust storm heading your way.
You'll need to head due north
within the hour.
Acknowledged.
Paris out.
Captain, I'm getting more
detailed sensor readings
on the approaching asteroid.
It's huge, over half
a kilometer in diameter,
and it's moving faster
than the others.
Time to impact?
Approximately two hours.
( breathing heavily )
Doctor, I'm going
to inject you
with a triox compound.
It will help to
oxygenate your blood.
( coughing )
I've prepared
an injection of...
Yes, uh, I know.
I heard you.
It...
won't be painful, will it?
No. It is a simple
subdermal transfer.
Oh, good. Good.
I... I despise needles.
Any progress with the...
with the converters?
We were unable to salvage
the damaged tank.
But Lillias is working
to increase the efficiency
of the functioning one.
And if she can't,
we'll all suffocate.
It is illogical
to dwell on situations
beyond your control.
It will only serve
to heighten your anxiety,
which, if I may say so,
is heightened enough.
Oh. Well, thank you
for the reassurance.
( breathing heavily )
How is everybody?
They are suffering
the initial stages
of carbon dioxide
poisoning.
And you?
My lungs are capable
of respirating
in an extremely thin atmosphere.
Then if we can't fix
this air supply,
you may be the only one left
to pilot this thing.
I'd better start
showing you
how to use the
ascent thrusters.
They must be kept
at a minimum temperature--
Stop!
What are you doing?
Get away.
I've got to get out.
Let me out.
Let go of me.
I need it.
So, now he wants to leave.
Let him.
No, you don't understand.
There's something
out there.
What is out there?
On...
the roof.
( groaning )
TUVOK:
He's going into shock.
( steady tone sounds
from tricorder )
He's dead.
Can you revive him?
His cardiopulmonary tissues
have begun to deteriorate.
From lack of oxygen?
No.
I believe he was murdered.
Murdered? How?
Poisoning.
According
to my tricorder readings,
his water supply
has been
contaminated with
a lydroxide corrosive.
Lydroxide?
That's the coolant used
in the tether couplings.
How do you know
it wasn't an accident?
The coolant system
is completely sealed,
and there is no lydroxide
anywhere else on board.
Now we have a choice
between death by suffocation
or death by poisoning.
I will conduct
an investigation
once we return
to the ship.
For now, we must
focus on survival.
HANJUAN:
Again you take command.
Again
you decide our fate.
How do we know you
didn't kill him?
TUVOK:
I have no motive.
HANJUAN:
Your motive would be the
same as ours, revenge.
TUVOK:
I am Vulcan.
I do not succumb
to emotion.
Oh, and we are expected
to believe that.
I think we should stop
the carriage.
Why?
Something Dr. Vatm said...
about getting up on the roof.
Dr. Vatm was delirious
from lack of oxygen.
He attempted to open the hatch
of this vessel and go outside.
It would have killed him
and possibly all of us as well.
Exactly. He was desperate enough
to risk his own life.
I think we should go up and find
out what he was talking about.
If we stop the carriage,
we'll risk losing
mag-lev cohesion again.
We'll check the roof
upon returning to Voyager.
I don't know.
I've got a funny feeling
about this.
I'm not interested
in your funny feeling.
You're not listening
to what I'm saying.
Delirious or not, he said
he needed whatever's up there.
What if it's something
that can help us?
I will not debate this with you.
Please pilot the craft
and remain silent.
You're going to listen to me!
( equipment powering down )
You are becoming
emotionally distraught.
There is little point in
furthering this discussion.
I'll tell you
who's being emotional. You.
You hide it beneath
that Vulcan calm,
but the truth is, you're filled
with contempt and sarcasm
and I'm tired of being the
target of all your hostility.
You are mistaken.
LILLIAS: No, he's not.
I can see it every time
you talk to Neelix.
You're dismissive
and condescending.
You are projecting your own
emotional bias onto my actions.
I have no feelings
toward Mr. Neelix.
That's right! That's exactly
what I'm talking about!
You have no feelings
for me,
but you have feelings
against me.
For three years,
you've ridiculed me
and made it obvious
to everyone
that you have
no respect for me,
and I've tolerated it.
You know why?
Because you are smarter
than I am, Tuvok,
and more logical
and... stronger
and superior
in almost every way.
And I admire you,
but you don't have
any instincts.
You don't have
any gut feelings,
and you don't really
understand people.
But non-Vulcans
have feelings,
and they have
to listen to them.
And I've got to listen to mine,
and right now,
they're telling me we need
to get up on that roof
and find out what the Doctor
was talking about.
I disagree.
Fine!
But I'm the only one
who can pilot this vessel
and we're not going anywhere
till someone
goes up on that roof.
You leave me little choice.
All right, then...
now... one of us
needs to go outside.
I'm not going out there.
Don't even think
about me.
I'm willing to give it--
I will go.
You?
I am the logical one
to make the egress.
I can breathe the
rarefied atmosphere.
I can't believe
you're going out there.
You don't even know
what you're looking for.
I am looking for
Mr. Neelix's instinct.
Perhaps it will be marked.
It's strange...
but I really like him.
( hatch opening )
I just wish the feeling
were mutual.
Tuvok to Neelix.
Go ahead.
I have found
a data storage device
lodged in the internal
circuitry.
It appears
to contain information
about an alien starship.
But I will need to remove it and
bring it into the cabin
for further examination.
Be careful up there.
If you can't remove it, don't.
( air whooshes )
Sklar! What are you doing?!
( both grunting )
LILLIAS:
Neelix!
( groans )
( hatch closes )
Where's Tuvok?
Mr. Tuvok
returned to the surface.
Get this carriage moving.
What are you...?
Now!
He can't.
He's hurt.
Back away.
Get up.
Get up!
( groaning softly )
Well... we're going to
have to figure out
how to fly this vessel.
Captain, the asteroid
is within visual range.
Let's see it.
Ensign.
There's a large crew complement.
At least 2,000.
They remodulated their shields
to fool our sensors.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
The Etanian Order
claims this territory.
You will withdraw.
This planet belongs
to the Nezu.
They have five
colonies here.
You are not Nezu.
I'm a friend of theirs,
Kathryn Janeway, and
I'm not going anywhere
until you've lowered
your weapons.
You will be willing to die
for them?
A loyal friend
and a foolish one.
They'll be here
in under ten minutes, Captain.
Battle stations.
( groans )
SKLAR:
Why haven't we started?
LILLIAS:
If we don't get moving soon,
the tether couplings
will give out. They'll snap.
We'll lose
mag-lev cohesion.
Then get us moving.
I can't! I don't know how.
SKLAR:
There's the accelerator control.
Try it.
LILLIAS:
Too dangerous. We've got to
secure the tether first.
SKLAR:
All right, you,
go outside
and check the couplings. Make
sure they haven't given out.
HANJUAN:
I'm not going out there.
Besides, I wouldn't know
what to look for.
LILLIAS:
The only person who knows how
to pilot this ship is Neelix.
SKLAR:
It can't be that complicated!
Keep trying.
LILLIAS:
I'm doing my best.
SKLAR:
Come on, come on, come on.
( screaming )
I'm glad you're all right.
Fortunately, I was able
to grab hold of
an induction coil
and climb to safety.
Thank you, Mr. Neelix.
What?
I said thank you
for opening the door.
Don't mention it.
I believe we know now
who killed Dr. Vatm.
But why did he kill him?
TUVOK:
The data storage
device contains
tactical information
about an alien starship.
Weapons, warp drive,
shield modulations.
Apparently, Sklar
did not want us to find it.
You have an occipital
concussion.
I'm afraid my understanding of
Talaxian physiology is limited.
I cannot treat you.
I don't know
how to do this.
We're going to lose cohesion
any minute now.
Neelix. We need you.
( groans )
I don't think
I can do it.
You must.
I can barely keep
my eyes open.
Do it...
for Alixia.
She would be proud of you.
I'm glad to see
your interpersonal
skills are improving.
You're learning how
to motivate people.
Speed: 45 kilometers per hour.
CHAKOTAY:
The ship is within range.
They're charging weapons.
Full power to the shields.
Ready phasers.
Shields down to 85 percent!
Return fire.
No effect.
We can't penetrate
their shields.
Hang on!
We're breaking through
the ionosphere!
Engaging induction dampers.
We did it.
We made it.
( chuckling )
Tuvok to Voyager.
Janeway here.
Are you all right, Lieutenant?
Yes, Captain.
We're a little busy right now.
Prepare to beam aboard.
Shields down to 23 percent.
Structural integrity is failing.
Captain.
This data device contains
tactical information
about the enemy vessel,
including their
shield modulation.
Adjust our phasers to match.
Target their primary reactor.
Ready.
Fire at will.
Direct hit.
Their reactor is off-line.
CHAKOTAY:
They're remodulating
their shields.
Target their weapons array.
Fire.
Their weapons
have been destroyed.
They're retreating,
Captain.
What happened to you
down there?
Where's Sklar?
Mr. Sklar...
returned to the surface.
I've just come
from a staff briefing.
The people who attacked
your colonies,
they call themselves
the Etanian Order.
Apparently, they
have a unique way
of invading other worlds.
First, they create
what appears to be
a natural disaster.
In your case,
an asteroid bombardment.
Once the population
has evacuated,
they arrive
and stake their claim.
But they didn't expect
Voyager to intervene,
so they arrived before our
colonies had been evacuated.
Exactly.
What about Dr. Vatm?
From what
we could tell,
Dr. Vatm found out
about the Etanian Order
and was secretly
collecting information
about their starship technology.
He also knew
that one of your colonists
was a traitor,
helping the Etanians,
feeding your government false
information about the asteroids.
But he didn't know
that it was Sklar.
He didn't know who to trust.
That's why he tried to hide the
data storage device on the roof.
The damage to our world
could have been much worse.
Thank you.
I have just received word
from the ambassador.
Your sister, Halla,
has been found.
( gasping )
Tell her I said hello.
Mr. Neelix.
I thought you should know
that I have submitted
my mission report
to the Captain.
I have given you
a special commendation
for your endurance
and bravery.
I'm honored.
Your instincts were correct.
However, one day,
your intuition will fail,
and you will finally understand
that logic is primary
above all else.
Instinct is simply another term
for "serendipity."
And one day,
Mr. Vulcan,
I'll get you
to trust your gut.
That is doubtful.
We'll see.
Your attempts
have yet to succeed.
You always have to get in
that last word, don't you?
I am simply responding
to your erroneous statement.
Something tells me
you just hate to lose
an argument.
Losing is irrelevant.
See what I mean?
No... I do not.