Let's mark the coordinates
of that trinary star.
It'll be a good reference
point for this sector.
Didn't we
already pass
a trinary system
like this?
Not that I remember. Why?
It just seems familiar.
Perhaps you're experiencing
a paradoxical
state-dependent
associative phenomenon.
Déjà vu.
( soft chuckle )
Yeah, I-I guess so.
( monitor beeps )
Captain, there is
a ship approaching,
bearing 215 mark 8.
On screen.
Their shields are down
and their weapon systems
are unpowered.
They're hailing us.
MALE:
My respects to you.
I'm Alben,
Captain of the Nerada.
Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
I thought I was familiar
with every type of ship
in this sector,
but I've never seen
anything like yours before.
We're not from around here.
In that case,
let me welcome you
to Nasari territory.
That ship's going to fire.
What?
Captain, we've got
to defend ourselves.
I am detecting no threat.
Tactical control
has been routed
to the Ops station.
Our weapon systems
are charging.
Raising shields
and firing phasers.
TUVOK:
Direct hit.
They are returning fire.
Red Alert!
( alarm blaring )
( dramatic
theme music playing )
Hail them. We've got to
put a stop to this.
Captain, I had
to act quickly.
You will explain
yourself, Mr. Kim,
but right now,
you're relieved.
Commander, you're at Ops.
TUVOK: They are not
responding to hails.
There's pressure building up
in Plasma Conduit G-6.
Ashmore, open up
the emergency vents.
I'll try to reroute
the plasma flow.
Shields are down to 70 percent.
Get us out of here.
CHAKOTAY:
Warp engines are down.
They are in pursuit.
Bridge to Engineering. What's
the status of the warp drive?
The plasma injectors
are off-line, Cap--
We're working on them now.
( both gasp )
A plasma conduit
just blew in Engineering.
Propulsion systems are down.
They're reporting
casualties.
Target their weapons array
and fire.
They've suffered damage
to their weapon systems
and shield emitters.
They are moving away.
( sighs )
I want to know exactly
what you thought you were doing.
Their weapons were charging.
They were about to fire at us.
We could have been
destroyed.
Sensor logs indicate that their
weapon systems were not powered.
Then they must have fooled
our sensors somehow.
I detected a tetryon surge
coming from their ship.
There are many possible sources
of increased tetryon emissions.
It may have been an irregularity
in their warp field.
No.
It was their weapons.
That whole "welcome to Nasari
territory" was a trick.
How could you know that?
I can't explain that.
I just knew.
I was only trying
to protect the ship.
I trust your
intentions, Ensign,
but your actions
are going to need
a little more
justification.
I want you to analyze
the sensor logs,
and see if there's any
basis for Mr. Kim's hunch.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
In the meantime,
I'm suspending you from duty.
Go to Sick Bay.
Let the Doctor have
a look at that cut.
Still no respiration.
Her blood pressure is
90/40 and dropping.
She has second-degree
burns on her lungs.
I'll need to do
a pulmonary regeneration.
Her neural tissues are
starting to degenerate.
Oxygen deprivation--
we've got to get her breathing.
Try ten milligrams
pulmozine.
( crew members coughing )
No effect.
20 milligrams.
( gasping )
Is she going
to be all right?
Yes. Another patient
snatched from the jaws of death.
Let me take care of that.
B'Elanna almost got killed.
It's my fault.
What do you mean?
I started that fight.
I thought I was doing
the right thing.
For a moment,
I was absolutely sure.
And now you're not?
It's fading.
What I did and how I felt--
it doesn't make any sense.
And it could
have been worse.
What if they'd been more
powerful than we were?
I could have
gotten everyone killed.
But none of that
happened.
B'Elanna got hurt,
and she'll recover.
Harry, you can't undo
what's been done.
You're right.
Thanks.
Raising shields
and firing phasers.
I can't explain it;
I just knew.
I never wanted
you to get hurt.
That's supposed to make me
feel better?
I'm sorry.
Harry, I'm here.
Don't worry.
You'll feel better soon.
I can make
some soup for you.
Would you like that?
I won't go anywhere
as long as you need me.
We raised you to be
a responsible boy.
I try to be.
I'm suspending you from duty.
Mom...
Well, the good news is
I won't have to quarantine you.
There's no sign of an infectious
agent anywhere in your body.
And the bad news?
If I don't find
the cause of this rash,
it will be difficult
to treat.
Last night, I had a dream
about being sick
with the Mendakan pox
when I was nine.
Do you think this
could be a recurrence?
I've never considered dreams
as a diagnostic tool before.
Your unconscious mind
sensed these developing symptoms
and tried to provide
an explanation?
Hm. Such recurrences of this
particular illness are rare,
but I will consider
the possibility.
( device beeping )
Hm.
What?
In addition to your
visible symptoms,
your blood chemistry has
been slightly altered.
Is that serious?
No, but
it's not consistent
with the symptoms
of the Mendakan pox.
Doctor, you don't think
there could be any, uh...
psychological effects
from this disease, do you?
Such as...?
I've been having this
strange déjà vu feeling.
Then yesterday on the Bridge,
I had this sudden instinct
and I acted on it
by firing without orders.
I'd certainly call that
atypical behavior.
Your scans haven't shown
any neurological abnormalities,
but I will run
a closer analysis.
Doctor, she's
regaining consciousness.
Good morning, Lieutenant.
( groans )
Morning?
What am I doing here?
There was an accident
in Engineering.
A plasma conduit exploded.
I've treated you for second
and third degree burns
and several
broken ribs.
I expect you'll make
a full recovery.
( groans )
After you've spent at least
one more day in Sick Bay.
This time, Doctor,
I'm not going to argue with you.
Harry.
What happened to your face?
We're still trying
to figure that out.
It's kind of cute.
Makes you look like
a speckled targ.
( laughs, then coughs )
B'Elanna...
I'm really sorry you got hurt.
Hey, it's all part
of the adventure
of space travel, right?
I know, but, um...
What? What is it?
Never mind.
I'm glad you're going
to be all right.
Thanks.
I'm afraid I'm going to have to
cut visiting hours short.
Ensign, you can go.
I'll contact you with
the results of my analysis.
Take care of yourself.
See you later, Spot.
( chuckles )
Captain...
I accept full responsibility
for my mistake.
I was completely out of line,
even if I believed that
other ship was charging weapons,
which they probably weren't.
Harry, they were
charging weapons.
I was right.
Tuvok has confirmed
that the tetryon surge
matched the energy signature
of that particulate beam
they shot at us.
They would have taken us
completely by surprise.
As soon as I saw their ship,
I felt this sudden...
suspicion and loathing.
I knew we were in trouble.
Which brings us back to
the larger question.
How did I know?
I really wish I could
tell you, Captain, but...
for the past few days,
this area of space
has seemed more and more
familiar to me.
If I didn't know
it was impossible,
I'd swear I've been here before.
We'll have to consider
every possible explanation.
Oh, believe me, I have been--
space-time anomalies,
alien telepathy,
alternate realities...
The list gets weirder
as it goes on.
Then there's
your sudden illness,
which may not be
a coincidence.
Tuvok to Janeway.
There are three ships
approaching
of the same configuration
as the Nasari vessel.
On my way.
They'll intercept
in 36 minutes.
Can we outrun them?
I doubt it.
Engineering's still
working on repairs.
We could manage
warp 3 at best.
Let me see a star chart
of this region.
Head for this system.
I think we can make it.
Is this another
hunch, Ensign?
We'll be safe there.
I'm sure of it.
Tactical status.
The aft shield emitter
is off-line.
Phasers are operational,
but torpedo
launchers are not.
I strongly advise
against a confrontation.
Follow Harry's course.
Speed-- as fast as we can go.
TUVOK:
The Nasari vessels
will overtake us
in two minutes.
We're coming up
on that star system.
We'll pass it if
we stay at warp.
Slow to impulse.
We're making our stand here.
They'll enter weapons range
in a few seconds.
Taresia.
What does that mean?
Do you know this place?
Yes. It was in my dream.
There is
another ship approaching
from the third planet.
Is it Nasari?
No, but they're
on an intercept course
and their weapons
are fully powered.
Prepare for
evasive maneuvers.
CHAKOTAY:
Aye, Captain.
We'll be all right.
The unidentified vessel
has disabled
all the Nasari ships.
They are retreating.
What's your next
trick, Harry--
pull a shuttlecraft
out of a hat?
Open a channel to that ship.
They're already hailing us.
FEMALE:
Alien vessel.
This is
the Taresian starship.
There you are.
Our sensors detected you
aboard your ship.
I'm glad to see you're safe.
Do you know me?
In a way.
I know you are
one of my people.
What?
You are Taresian.
Welcome home.
JANEWAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 50732.4.
The Taresians have escorted us
back to their homeworld
so we can continue
to investigate their claim
that Ensign Kim
is a member of their race.
FEMALE:
Welcome.
We're so glad
to have you here.
This is a day
of celebration.
Another Taresian
has returned.
Welcome.
You're home
now, Harry.
Uh, wait a minute.
I still don't understand
how this is possible.
We'd like to ask
some questions
before we start
celebrating.
Of course.
Our doctor has found
some genetic fragments in my DNA
which could be part
of an alien genetic structure.
Yes, those are
your Taresian genes.
They're becoming active.
We'd be happy
to provide your doctor
with some DNA samples
for comparison.
What I want to know is
how I could have gotten them.
You were conceived here
on this world.
While you were still
an embryo,
you were placed in stasis
and taken to Earth
to be implanted in the womb
of an Earth woman.
My mother.
What did you do to her?
She would
have been completely
unaware
of the procedure.
After the implantation process,
the child begins to incorporate
some DNA
from the surrogate parent.
You developed physically
as a human,
so she would have thought
you were her natural child.
But you're saying I'm not.
We understand
how you feel.
Everyone here was born
on other worlds.
We all found our way
back home, like you,
and discovered we're not quite
who we thought we were.
Harry, maybe you'd
like to sit down.
Why don't you go get him
something to drink?
All of your children are
born to alien parents?
Yes.
And when they return,
each child brings an infusion
of new genetic material,
as well as years
of firsthand experience
about another culture.
But Harry wasn't trying
to return here.
We came to the Delta Quadrant
by accident.
His DNA was encoded
with certain instincts,
including the desire
to explore space.
Your "accident"
may have brought
him here faster,
but he always would have been
driven to find his way back.
You are the first to return
from such a great distance.
Harry...
That's how Taresians say
thank you, isn't it?
But how could I know so much
about a place I've never been?
It's been coded
into your Taresian genes.
As you've gotten
closer to home
and seen familiar sights,
your dormant genetic memory
has been
reawakened.
You'll remember more about us
as you spend time here.
I know it all seems strange now,
but you are one of us, Harry.
Can't you feel it?
Yes.
I can.
Then stay with us a while
and celebrate.
Come, have something to eat.
Is this the standard
welcome home reception?
For males, it is.
They're very rare.
Our population is
90 percent female.
Really?
I want to thank you again
for your help
in combating the Nasari.
Do you have any idea
why they tried to attack us?
They probably detected
a Taresian
aboard your ship,
as we did.
For the Nasari, that's
reason enough to destroy you.
Are your people
at war?
We have no interest
in fighting with them,
but they seem determined
to destroy us.
Our defense capabilities prevent
them from attacking directly,
but they do
everything in their power
to stop our people
from returning home.
TUVOK:
I see.
That might explain
Mr. Kim's instinctively
hostile reaction to them.
It's a defense mechanism
we've programmed
into all our children.
Are the Nasari likely
to attack us again
when we leave your space?
I think eventually they'll tire
of waiting for you to come out.
In the meantime, I'd advise you
to simply stay here for a while.
KIM:
These are words.
Mm-hm.
Can you read them?
Almost.
Our written language
is very complicated.
I can teach it to you
if you're interested.
Oh, that looks good.
What is it?
Spiced hatana.
I prepared it myself.
Harry, try some.
I'd like to find out
if I have any relatives here.
Maybe talk
to my biological parents.
I'm afraid none of us get
the chance
to meet our fathers.
They're the ones who take
the embryos to other worlds.
Your father must
have left here
a very long time ago
to make it all the way
to the Alpha Quadrant.
Ensign, we're transporting
back to the ship.
I'd like to stay
for a while.
I still have
a lot of questions.
Of course, Harry.
Contact us
when you're ready.
We'll see you later.
DOCTOR:
It's a positive match.
These genetic fragments
within Ensign Kim's DNA
are clearly Taresian.
Why haven't they shown up
in his medical scans before?
I went back and checked
his scans carefully.
These fragments have apparently
been disguising themselves
as the recessive elements
which normally exist
within all DNA,
but over the past few days,
they've become
increasingly dominant
over his human genes.
And they provided him
with new knowledge.
Yes, by forming neural
connections in his brain.
All humanoid babies
are born with certain
instinctive knowledge--
how to recognize
the shape of a face,
how to hold their
breath underwater.
It all comes from their genes.
The Taresians must have
found a way to manipulate
genetic material to implant
very specific knowledge
into their children.
It's scientifically plausible,
but quite a feat
of genetic engineering.
So what the Taresians
have been telling us
appears to be true.
Harry is
one of their people.
And he's becoming more like them
every day, both physically
and neurologically.
I wonder how that's
going to influence him
when Voyager's ready to leave?
Of course,
when that might happen
is another question entirely.
Are the Nasari
still out there?
All three ships
are holding position
just outside the
Taresian system.
Even if we can't
wait them out,
we may only be postponing
another conflict.
I'd much rather find a way
to convince them
we're not their enemies.
Apparently, the Nasari
only consider Ensign
Kim their enemy.
Perhaps they would
be more receptive
to diplomacy
if he were not aboard.
Contact Harry.
Let him know
we'll be leaving orbit.
With any luck, we'll
be back in a few hours
with this matter resolved.
I joined the merchant fleet
so I could get into space
because I wanted to explore
every corner of the galaxy.
Like me with Starfleet.
All my life that's
all I ever wanted to do.
Now I guess I know why.
Strange to think
that some alien DNA fragments
have been controlling my life.
MALE:
Not controlling.
Influencing, yes.
You probably inherited
some Taresian traits
like... a talent
for math or music.
Yes. I always wondered
why I loved music so much
when my parents--
my human parents--
were practically tone deaf.
Wait. Wait a minute.
What is that?
Something to make
you feel good.
It's just a mild
mood enhancer.
No side effects.
You'll like it.
I think I'll pass.
Thanks.
This is Malia.
She's going to be
my first wife.
First?
Uh-huh.
You're already planning
on a second?
And a third.
We'll all be joined
with Taymon tonight.
What do humans call it
when a man and
women are joined?
It's called marriage.
But it's usually
one woman with one man.
How unusual.
I hope you come
to our ceremony.
I wouldn't miss it.
Don't be afraid to
indulge yourself, Harry.
Everybody here wants
you to be happy.
You're important to us.
That's what my human parents
used to say to me--
how special I was.
They'd been trying
to have a baby for years
until I came along.
They called me
their "miracle child."
They were right.
They spoiled me rotten,
making sacrifices
so they could give me
everything I wanted.
Sounds like you
were pretty lucky.
They loved you.
But I never felt like
I deserved
that kind of devotion.
I didn't see what was
so special about me.
I used to imagine that
I had these hidden powers.
I'd grow up to be
stronger than a Klingon
or able to read
people's minds.
Anything to make me more
than just an average kid.
Turns out your parents
were right about you.
You have been special
all of your life.
Feels pretty good,
doesn't it?
Yeah.
It does.
Mm... Let me relax
your muscles for you.
Uh, that would be great.
( sighs )
I think you're going to learn
to like it here, Harry.
I already like it.
Enough to stay?
I don't know about that.
I'm happy where I am
on Voyager.
You could be
happy here, too.
It's nothing you have
to decide right now.
Just enjoy yourself
while you're here.
( chuckles )
This uniform seems
so restrictive.
Why don't you let me
find you something
more comfortable?
Thanks.
I mean...
I agree
with you completely, Captain.
There's no reason for further
hostility between us.
I'm glad to hear it,
and I hope you'll
still feel that way
when Ensign Kim
is back on board.
I doubt
we'll face that problem.
Your crew member
won't be returning to you.
What do you mean?
No one who "comes home"
to Taresia ever leaves again.
There are rumors
about those people.
I'm not interested
in hearsay.
Are there any facts
you can give me?
I fire
on any Taresian I see.
If you take
your crew member back on board,
I will attack your ship!
My best advice to you
is to forget him,
and be on your way.
Do you think
there's any truth
to those rumors
he mentioned?
I don't know,
but I'll feel better
when we've got Harry back.
Set a course
back to the planet.
Captain, sensors indicate
a high-density polaron grid
surrounding
the planet.
A polaron grid?
It wasn't here before.
A network of satellites
was activated to generate it.
Can we get
through the grid?
Unlikely.
The polaric density is too high.
Hail them.
Our communications
are being blocked.
I guess we're
not welcome anymore.
Don't worry.
You'll remember
everything you need to know
about the ceremony
once it begins.
Amal ulat.
Let us be joined.
The joining is complete.
Why do they tie him
like that?
It's tradition.
It symbolizes binding
their lives together,
no longer looking
for anyone else.
Do you find it exciting?
I guess I hadn't really
thought of it that way.
You are going to stay
for the celebration, aren't you?
Actually, I should check in
with Voyager.
They're probably back by now.
( sighs )
Kim to Voyager.
This is Ensign Kim
calling Voyager.
Do you read?
Harry... I'm glad you
could be here for this.
It's been interesting.
I was wondering if there's
been any word from Voyager.
Not that I know of.
They probably
haven't returned yet.
It's been a long time.
I hope they didn't run
into trouble with the Nasari.
Oh, try not to worry.
Your Captain may
need some time
to convince those
people to see reason.
Hm, maybe so.
Come... join the
celebration while you wait.
And of course you're
welcome to stay the night.
We've been able
to poke some holes
in the tachyon grid,
but they're too small
to squeeze Voyager through.
Could a shuttle
make it?
I doubt it, and even if one
could, there's another problem--
a Taresian ship is patrolling
the other side of the grid.
And we saw
what they can do.
Ah, Captain, when you
raised some concerns
regarding the Taresians,
I began questioning their story
about Ensign Kim's birth.
I thought you'd confirmed
that he has Taresian DNA.
I did... and he does...
at least, he does now.
But when I checked his
previous microcellular scans,
I found no traces of the
Taresian genetic fragments.
I can only conclude
that he wasn't born with them.
Their whole story about
embryo implantation was a lie.
He's human.
Yes, although
maybe not for long.
The alien DNA is continuing
to alter his genetic structure.
Within a few days,
he'll be indistinguishable
from a native Taresian.
Do you have any idea
how this new DNA
could have gotten into
his cells?
The most likely
transfer mechanism
would be a retrovirus.
He was probably exposed
during an away mission.
Wouldn't the biofilters pick up
the virus and eliminate it?
They may very well have.
But once the virus transferred
the DNA into his cells,
"killing the messenger"
wouldn't have helped.
Is there any way to determine
exactly when he was infected?
Indeed there is.
The transporter buffer
performs its own version
of a microcellular scan
every time someone uses it.
I reviewed the logs
and found the first appearance
of the alien genes
in his molecular pattern
on stardate 50698.
Our away mission
to that planet
where we found
the vorillium.
Harry was with us
and he was separated
from the group
for a while.
He might have been infected
by something he ate or drank,
even something
he touched.
So Harry gets infused
with alien DNA,
which gives him the instinctive
urge to come here.
Then the Taresians tell him
this elaborate story
to make him believe
he was one of them. Why?
Don't forget that welcoming
committee on the planet.
It sounds as if they're
giving him every incentive
to want to stay on Taresia.
And by keeping us away,
they're making the decision
for him.
Here you are.
I hope you'll be
comfortable here.
Is there anything else
that I can get for you?
No. I'll be fine.
Thanks.
Good night.
Get into bed.
You're going
to tuck me in?
"Tuck you in"?
It's a human custom.
Parents tuck their children
into bed, tell them a story,
or sing a lullaby to them
to help them get to sleep.
That's sweet.
Lie back and relax.
( chuckles )
Lekaria san.
Do you understand?
Pleasant dreams.
Mm-hm.
Now close your eyes.
Mm. That's smells good.
Mm-hm.
It's the essence
of rikka flowers.
It's very soothing.
Lekaria san.
Good night, Harry.
You're Taresian.
Welcome home.
I think you'll like it
here, Harry.
We've been lucky
to have you, Harry.
You really have been special
all your life.
You know where your
real home is, Harry.
I think you'll
like it here, Harry.
Stay with me.
It's all right. It's all right.
You were dreaming.
What are you doing here?
We just want to help you relax
and enjoy yourself.
Look, I appreciate
the offer,
but I'd really
rather be alone.
I don't believe that.
I think you've been spending
too many nights alone,
Harry.
You've got to stop
holding yourself back.
I know you have
the same natural desires
as any Taresian.
Now, you're free
to act on them.
You can't fight
genetics.
I can try.
I want you
to choose me, Harry.
Choose both of us,
then you'll only have
to find one more wife.
( chuckles )
I'm not joining with you
or with anybody.
But that's the reason why you
were drawn back home, Harry--
to have children.
Listen to your instincts.
No.
Like I told you before,
I'm going back to Voyager.
You could never be as valuable
to them as you are to us.
We need you.
You have a responsibility
to your people
to pass on your genes
to the next generation.
If there's anything your
Taresian genes have given you,
it's a sense
of duty and loyalty.
My loyalty is to my crew
and my family back home.
You don't belong
with them anymore.
This is who you are--
one of us.
Your place is here.
We'll make you glad
you stayed.
Think of Taymon,
how happy he's been.
Let yourself be happy.
It's the right choice,
Harry.
This is the life
you were always meant to have.
Maybe this life
wouldn't be so terrible.
( all chuckle )
It will be wonderful.
You'll have everything
you ever wanted
and a place of honor
among your people.
You'll never be alone
again, Harry.
We'll make sure of that.
Three wives?
Mm-hm.
Hm.
I've got to think
about my choice.
I know you're attracted to me.
There's been a connection
between us
since the moment you got here.
You're right.
I felt it, too.
I'm definitely considering you
as one of my wives.
What are you doing?
Well, it's like
you said before,
this could be exciting.
Remember, you both...
want to make me happy,
don't you?
This is some
kind of trick.
( grunts )
Sorry about that.
Shh!
( muffled speech )
( whispering ):
Taymon?
It's Harry.
I really need your help.
( buzzes )
Are you in there?
( gasps )
( door code beeping )
So is this what I should expect
on my honeymoon?
It would have been
much easier for you
if you hadn't seen this.
You mean easier for you
to lead me to the slaughter.
What did you do to Taymon?
We must denucleate
a large number of cells
to collect enough genetic
material for conception.
That's why
there are no men here.
They don't leave
with their embryos in stasis...
They're killed.
Any father should be willing
to sacrifice himself
for the sake of his children,
for the continuation
of his race.
Was anything
you told me true?
About Taresians being born
on other worlds,
about my being one of you?
It's true male children
are very rare here,
and that we seek out new DNA
to sustain our race.
We need males of other species--
like you--
who can be transformed
into compatible mates.
Transformed?
That's what these genes
are doing to me?
You'll be celebrated
for your contribution.
Don't count on it.
You're going to take me
to a communications terminal
where I can contact my ship.
( door code beeping )
( grunts )
KIM:
Stay out of my way.
This won't work.
You're too important
to us.
Whatever happens to me,
they won't allow
you to leave.
( all gasp )
CHAKOTAY:
If we hit the grid here,
we'll have a few seconds
before the patrol ship
can move in to intercept us.
That doesn't give you much time
to get a lock on Harry.
Then I'll have to be quick.
Are the shields ready?
The new configuration
is stable.
Set a course
for the target coordinates
and engage at full impulse.
Aye, Captain.
We're disrupting the grid,
but we need more speed
to overcome
the inertial resistance.
Increasing power.
We're clear.
I'm not picking up
Harry's com signal.
Initiating level-1
bio-scans of the surface.
Captain, the Taresian ship
is on an intercept course.
Battle stations.
( growling )
( screams )
This could have been
a joyous occasion.
Amal ulat!
Now!
I won't let you do this to me!
Harry, there's nowhere to go.
We've got him.
Setting a new course.
TUVOK:
The Taresians
are in pursuit.
Return fire.
Aye, sir.
Captain, we've got
another problem.
Three Nasari ships
coming straight at us.
Time till intercept?
PARIS:
Less than one minute.
Harry.
Captain.
Welcome back.
We could use your
strategic intuition about now.
JANEWAY: I'm counting
on the Taresians
not to back off
from those Nasari ships.
They won't.
Good.
Let's hope
they're more interested
in fighting
with each other than with us.
Five seconds to intercept.
We are no longer
being pursued.
Let's not give them a chance
to change their mind.
But Odysseus had been warned
that these women,
the sirens,
sang a song so beautiful
that any man who heard it
would be lured to his death.
So how did he get the ship
past them?
He told his crew
to cover their ears
so they couldn't hear
the sirens' song.
But he also had them tie him
to the mast of the ship
so he could listen himself
without being led astray
as they sailed past.
Anyone would have been drawn in
by these... Taresians.
I have never seen so many
beautiful women in my life.
It wasn't just
the women.
Oh...
( mumbles )
There was also
something exciting
about having a new identity,
being more than just
"young Ensign Kim."
Well, I, for one, am glad
to have a young Ensign Kim
back with us.
Although I still say
you should have kept
some of those spots.
I thought they were
very distinguished.
I don't see what's so bad
about being you.
You're good at your job,
everybody likes you.
Being likable is fine,
but sometimes I wish
I could be more bold,
confident with women--
more like you.
Like me?
You might want to
reconsider that, Harry.
There could be prison time
involved.
Actually, since
I've been on Voyager,
I've tried to be
more like you.
That'll be the day.
No, I'm serious.
You're my role model.
You're reliable,
hard-working,
extremely punctual.
Did I mention polite?
Heh, thanks a lot.
( dramatic
theme music playing )