DOCTOR: Activate
the bio-temporal chamber.
Is she going
to be all right?
Not if you don't all
clear out of here
and let me
do my work.
She's my mother.
I'm staying.
This is a very
delicate procedure
and I could use
some peace and quiet.
PARIS:
The Doctor's right.
Let's let him
do his work.
All right.
( labored breathing )
( door opens, closes )
I wish I'd told you this before,
but better late than never.
You're the finest friend
I've ever had.
Prepare to bring the
bio-temporal chamber on line.
We'll begin in approximately
five minutes.
Grandma, are you awake?
I brought you a present.
Grandma Kes?
( dramatic
theme music playing )
I finally finished making
your birthday present.
Sorry it's late,
but I wanted
to get it right.
I... I don't know you.
What do you mean?
I'm Andrew...
your grandson.
I don't know you.
Doctor.
Dr. van Gogh.
What is it?
She doesn't
recognize me.
Kes?
How are you feeling?
Where am I?
What is this place?
You're in Sick Bay.
Do you know who I am?
No.
Yes.
I've seen you before.
Do you know my name?
The boy, he called you
Dr. van Gogh.
That's right.
You said
I was your finest friend.
Well... I'm not sure
I've ever said that exactly,
but... that doesn't mean
it's not true.
How could I be your friend?
I don't know you.
Tell me what you do remember.
Uh, people around me,
crowded around me.
You, a boy, a young girl.
I was in a chamber...
A bio-temporal chamber.
Good.
I was inside it and you told
someone to activate it.
I'm afraid you're confused.
I discussed the bio-temporal
chamber with you,
but we're not ready
to put you inside it just yet.
Can you recall anything else
besides those people you saw?
Anything else about your life?
No.
Go find the rest
of your family.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What's the big hurry?
I'm sorry, Captain.
I have to go.
What was that
all about?
I'm afraid Kes is
getting worse, Captain.
Her amnesia
is near total.
Fewer than one percent
of her engrams
remained intact.
It's as if her memory
were wiped clean.
Is it some sort
of senility?
Maybe. I've
never treated
a nine-year-old
Ocampan before.
For all I know,
it's a perfectly normal part
of their aging process.
It's hard to believe
that she performed
microsurgery on my elbow
just a few weeks ago.
A few weeks ago,
she was a healthy woman,
but this morilogium
comes on abruptly
and then progresses
with a rapidity
I've never seen before.
How are you
coming along
with the bio-temporal
chamber?
As I told you, it's a completely
revolutionary procedure.
I have no idea
if it'll work.
Under normal circumstances,
I'd want to perform extensive
tests on the apparatus,
but we're losing her
too fast.
If I don't try it now,
it may be too late.
If you really believe
it will prolong her life...
If we're lucky, it may
buy her another year.
I think you have
the family's consent.
You should go ahead
and do it.
KES:
I'm so cold.
I'm cold.
No wonder.
Your temperature
has dropped to 14.8--
almost two degrees
below normal.
What does
that mean?
I'm not sure.
What?
Her cells are in a state
of bio-temporal flux.
I don't understand
how that could be happening
before I put her
in the chamber.
KES:
I'm cold.
( gasps )
( sighs )
ANDREW:
Look, Mom, I'm almost finished
with Grandma's present.
WOMAN:
It's wonderful, sweetheart.
I'm sure Grandma will think
it was well worth the wait.
ANDREW:
I hope so.
I still feel bad
about not having it ready
in time for her party.
Hello.
How was your nap?
Andrew?
Grandma,
don't look.
You'll ruin
the surprise.
Why don't you sit down?
I'll get you some tea.
Where am I?
In your quarters.
What quarters?
Aboard Voyager.
What's wrong?
I don't know who you are.
But you...
I know who you are.
Tell me what's happening.
How did I
get here?
Andrew, get your
grandfather and father.
Tell them to meet us
in Sick Bay.
Yes... Sick Bay.
I remember that place.
I was just there.
Uh, when?
Just a few minutes ago.
Dr. van Gogh
asked me some questions.
I couldn't remember
anything.
You haven't been to Sick
Bay for over a week--
since you stopped
working there.
Working?
What kind of work?
Don't you
remember?
You were one of
the ship's doctors.
I worked there with you.
Who are you?
I'm your daughter...
Linnis.
But I don't remember you.
Do you remember
anything at all?
Just people
crowded around me...
voices...
The Doctor told
everyone to leave
and then he told
someone else
to activate
the bio-temporal chamber.
He's been working
on that.
He may have
mentioned it to you.
And then I woke up
and there was a boy,
Andrew,
standing over me
with a present...
calling me Grandma.
But Andrew hasn't finished
your present yet.
You just saw him
still working on it
in your quarters.
But he was there.
The Doctor sent him
to get my family,
and I was cold,
and I woke up in that bed
in the quarters and...
Maybe you
were dreaming.
( sighs )
I... I don't think so.
Well, none of the things
that you remember
before waking from your nap
have happened.
How do you know?
Listen to me, Mother.
You're confused right now,
and I'm sure
that's very frightening.
But you need to trust me.
I'm your daughter
and I love you.
Now, please, come with me.
Come.
I've been
expecting this.
The onset of morilogium.
She's lost more than 98 percent
of her memory engrams.
Morilogium?
The final phase
of the Ocampan life-span,
Mother.
Are you saying
that I'm dying?
Not if I
can help it.
What do you mean?
Kes, it's me, Tom.
Your husband.
Tom.
We're losing her.
How long?
If we do nothing,
a matter of weeks.
But I'm working on something
to extend her life-span.
It involves treating her
with a bio-temporal field
in order to push
her cells back
to an earlier stage
of entropic decay.
It's highly experimental,
but if it works,
it might buy her some time.
No. My mother's
always accepted
that she would
only live nine years.
If she's reaching
the natural end of her life,
she wouldn't want extraordinary
measures taken to extend it,
especially not in the state
she's in now.
If the Doctor has a way
to keep your mother with us,
even for one more day,
we have to let him try.
We're not talking about
a tested medical procedure here.
We're talking about
a radical experiment.
Sweetheart, I understand
how upsetting this is.
But if it were you
on that bio-bed,
I'd feel just like Tom does.
KES: Everyone, listen
to me, please.
LINNIS:
Yes, listen to her.
Mother, tell us
what you want.
I want to know
what's going on here.
Maybe the morilogium
is causing my amnesia,
but that doesn't explain
how I seem to suddenly jump
from Sick Bay to my quarters,
or how I remember being
in a bio-temporal chamber.
Kes, it's possible
the morilogium
is causing you
to experience delusions.
No, they're not
delusions!
I want you to lie down.
No.
Leave her alone.
Your grandmother's
very sick, son.
Maybe, but she's
not delusional.
She's the smartest
person I know.
We should listen
to her.
Oh, I'm cold.
Her body temperature
has dropped 2.7 degrees.
ALL: ♪ ...For she's
A jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For she's
♪ For she's a jolly good
Fellow ♪
♪ Which nobody
Can deny ♪♪
Happy ninth, Kes.
Well, go ahead.
Make a wish.
Well, what are
you waiting for?
Blow out the candles.
It's good to see that old lung
is still working, Kessy.
Happy birthday,
sweetheart.
Why, you know, I haven't
made one of these
since... well, since
I became Security Officer.
Perhaps you would care
to relinquish your commission
and return to the scene
of your former triumphs.
You keep working
on that sense of humor,
Commander Vulcan.
You'll get it
one of these days.
Jimbalian fudge--
your favorite.
Some of us ought to be
watching our calories,
but after all, it is
a special occasion.
Andrew.
I'm sorry I don't have
a present for you, Grandma.
I've got an idea
for something special
I'm going to make,
but I've been
too busy with
schoolwork.
I haven't had
a chance to start it.
I think it'll be
worth the wait.
Come and talk to Grandma
for a minute, will you?
Sure.
I'm going to ask
you a few questions
and I want you
to think very carefully
before you answer them,
all right?
I always think
before I speak.
You taught me that.
Where were you before you
came to this party?
At my physics lesson
in Engineering.
And then you came
directly here?
No. I stopped at
your quarters to get you.
Don't you remember?
Andrew, stop monopolizing
your grandmother's time.
There are other people
who'd would like to wish her
a happy birthday,
you know.
She's all
yours, Doctor.
Excuse me.
That cake looks great.
It's amazing to think
that you weren't
even a year old
when we first met.
Not much older
than Andrew.
Doctor, there's
something wrong with me.
What is it?
Promise to hear me out
and not assume
I'm delusional.
Why do you think I'd ever
make such an assumption?
Promise.
Of course.
I've lost all
but a few of my memories,
and the memories
I do have
don't coincide
with anyone else's.
Can you be
more specific?
Well, I was in Sick Bay
and you and a woman,
my daughter,
were arguing about
prolonging my life,
and then I suddenly
appeared in my quarters,
and then I simply
appeared here.
As far as I know,
none of that happened.
Is it possible
you were dreaming?
No. I was awake.
I'm sure of it.
But nobody else remembers
the things I do.
I hate to say this,
but... it's possible
that these strange experiences
you're having
are related to the onset
of the morilogium.
You talked about that.
You wanted to put me
in a bio-temporal chamber
to stop my aging process.
How could you possibly
know about that?
Because you told me.
I only came up
with the idea
for the bio-temporal chamber
this morning.
I was going to
tell you about it today,
here, at the party as a sort of
birthday surprise.
If that were true, then how
could I already know about it?
I don't know,
but we'd better get you
to Sick Bay
and find out.
She appears to have lost
more than 95 percent
of her memory engrams.
Is that symptomatic
of the morilogium?
I don't know.
I have no basis
for comparison.
No other Ocampans
on board.
Don't worry.
We'll get to the
bottom of this.
I do have memories.
They just don't coincide
with anyone else's.
First, Andrew gave me
a belated birthday present.
Then, he said he was
working on the present.
And now he just apologized
for not starting it yet.
It's almost as if
you're experiencing
events in reverse.
Maybe there's some kind
of time paradox at work.
There is another
possibility.
Given that Kes
has knowledge
of a treatment I have not
yet devised, it's possible
she's developed some
sort of precognition.
Are you saying I can see
into the future?
Well, you've
demonstrated some
pretty extraordinary
mental powers
over the years--
telepathy, telekinesis.
And precognition wouldn't
be unprecedented.
Some species, including the
Yattho of the Beta Quadrant,
have been known to
predict future events
with uncanny accuracy.
See if you can confirm this
theory about precognition.
In the meantime,
Tom and I will begin
scanning
for temporal anomalies.
We'll do everything
we can to help you.
I'd like to do something
to help myself.
What did you
have in mind?
Well, I seem to have lived
quite a full life on this ship.
Maybe if I had a look
at my medical files
or checked other records
of my activities,
I might be able
to fill in some of the blanks.
Well, you may have lost
your memories,
but you certainly haven't
lost your determination.
Hi.
Oh, hello.
How's it coming?
I've had a busy life.
It's hard to know
where to start.
How about you?
Well, we've tried
every kind of temporal scan
Harry could think of,
but we still haven't
been able to find anything
to explain what's
been happening to you.
Your initial physical exam.
I remember
when you came on board.
I had a crush on you
right from the beginning.
I tried to hide it,
but Neelix sensed it
and, boy, was
he ever jealous.
Neelix?
You don't remember?
( sighs )
You and he were
involved for quite a while.
( clears throat )
Oh, one of your
prenatal exams.
When we listened
to Linnis's heartbeat.
That was quite a day.
What about this?
It says I got some kind
of radiation poisoning
on stardate 50973.
That was
the beginning
of the Year of Hell.
"Year of Hell"?
Well, that's what some of us
call it now.
We were
under virtually constant attack
by a race called the Krenim.
The ship almost didn't make it.
The Doctor was off-line
for months,
and we lost
a lot of good people--
Captain Janeway,
Joe Carey... B'Elanna.
B'Elanna?
I keep forgetting that you
don't remember any of them.
B'Elanna was...
someone
who was very special to me.
When she died,
I felt like
I wanted to die, too.
But you...
you helped me
through it.
I'm sorry.
No.
No. It's my fault.
You haven't done
anything wrong. It's just...
You don't remember
any of our life together?
Well, that's all right.
I've got enough feelings
for both of us.
Maybe the feelings
I had for you will come back.
You were asking
about the radiation
poisoning.
A lot of us
were exposed.
During the first
Krenim attack,
one of the chroniton
torpedo fragments
leaked radiation into the ship.
Chroniton torpedoes?
They were able to
penetrate our shields
because their torpedoes
were in a constant state
of temporal flux.
Wait a minute...
I think we may be
onto something.
We'd better go talk
to the Doctor.
Come on.
If I was infected with
these chroniton particles,
there might be a connection
to what's happening to me now.
Exactly.
Maybe we should try
scanning for residual...
KIM:
Say cheese.
Oh...
I think he's got
your nose, Mother.
So how does it feel
to be a grandfather?
A lot better than it does
to have you for a son-in-law.
What's the date?
The date?
Yes. The stardate.
It's 56947. Why?
Over six months.
Mother, what's going on?
Tom, we have to
talk to the Doctor.
Come on.
As far as I can tell,
I've jumped backwards
a total of five times
so far.
Is there any discernible
pattern to these jumps?
No. They're
apparently random.
Uh, one time it seemed
to span for a few weeks
and the last
was half a year.
Each time I arrive, I seem
to exist in temporal sync
with the rest of you
for a while,
but before I can make anyone
understand what's happening,
I find myself
at an earlier time in my life,
and just before it happens,
I seem to experience
a sudden drop
in body temperature.
( beeping )
Hm...
Now, this could explain
a thing or two.
What is it?
I'm detecting high-level
chroniton radiation
in your cells.
So I was right.
There is a connection.
But Kes was
inoculated
along with the
rest of the crew
over three years ago.
Yes, however, everyone was left
with trace amounts of the
radiation in their bodies.
For some reason,
those residual chronitons
have reactivated in Kes.
Why?
The bio-temporal chamber.
My thinking exactly.
Would you two
mind explaining?
It's really quite
obvious, Lieutenant.
Your wife is traveling
backward through time.
It's as though
I came into existence
at the moment
of my own death
without any memories.
I've been living my life
backwards ever since--
jumping progressively
to earlier moments in my life,
accumulating memories
and experiences as I go.
Your past has become
my future.
Doctor, any theory about
what's causing this?
In approximately six months,
I will apparently expose Kes
to some type
of bio-temporal field
in a highly experimental, but
nonetheless brilliant attempt
to stop her aging process.
And it's this attempt
which leads
to Kes's current predicament?
What I will, apparently,
fail to realize
is that the bio-temporal field
is going to reactivate
the dormant chroniton particles
in her cells,
bringing Kes out of temporal
sync with the rest of us.
Is there any way
to stop Kes
from continuing
these jumps?
Yes. Purge her completely
of the chroniton poisoning.
KIM: To do that,
we'd need to know
the precise
temporal variance
of the specific torpedo
which contaminated the ship.
Tactical sensors were not
functioning at the time.
There is no data regarding
the torpedo in question.
PARIS: Let me get one
thing straight, Doc.
Is it possible, if this
keeps happening to Kes
that she might actually
jump back into a time
before she
knew any of us?
DOCTOR: Worse than that,
Mr. Paris.
It's possible she may
eventually jump back
to a time...
before she even existed.
CHAKOTAY: Captain's Log,
Stardate 55836.2.
Kes has remained
in temporal sync with us
for two days now,
but since we don't know
when she may jump again,
we can't afford to rest
until we've found some way
to help her.
I'm going to try running
a hypothalamic scan.
Maybe we can
establish a pattern
to the drops in your
body temperature.
You're very good
at this, aren't you?
I had a very good teacher.
Doctor van Gogh?
You.
I'm sorry. All this
must be taking you
away from your baby
just now.
You must be wanting to spend
every second with him.
Actually, I feel a little
awkward around him sometimes.
Harry's always
singing to him
and playing with him, but...
Well, I seem to be
much more comfortable
with a molecular scanner
than I am with a diaper.
Oh, Linnis,
I don't think that...
Kes, I may have found a way
to prevent your next jump.
I've erected a containment field
that may keep you here.
It's going to require
your confinement in Sick Bay.
I'll keep working here.
Linnis... you must
be a good mother.
I happen to know
that Andrew grows up
to be a wonderful child.
Hello, Tom.
I thought... maybe you
could use some company.
I feel like I'm in a cage.
Dr. van Gogh says...
Dr. "van Gogh"?
I thought you
settled on "Mozart."
Evidently, my interest
in the great figures
of art and culture
will be an ongoing process.
Well...
"Vincent", uh...
how about letting me
inside this thing?
I'm afraid that wouldn't
be advisable.
( sighing ):
Okay, then...
How about another
installment of
Tom and Kes:
The Early Years?
I'd enjoy that.
Um...
Well, there was, uh,
our wedding reception.
Harry was my best man.
Heh. He...
He got so nervous
when he stood up
to give the toast
that he spilled champagne
all over my dress uniform.
( laughing )
What is it?
At the time,
I thought that was
the happiest day of my life...
but every day
just got better and better.
It means so much
to have you here now.
( door opens )
I think I may have
found something.
What is it?
Well, I was
studying the effects
of the chronitons on
other crew members and I...
( alarm sounding )
PARIS:
What's that?
Kes' temperature
has dropped 1.9 degrees.
Linnis, monitor
the containment field.
I'm going to try to elevate
her temperature.
Her temperature's
still dropping.
We're losing containment.
Increase the field
amplitude.
Kes...?
It's not working.
DOCTOR:
We're losing her.
Set field polarization
to maximum!
Do something!
( panting )
The sac is opening...
What's happening?
What do you mean,
"What's happening?"
You're having a baby.
Now, hold still.
Where am I?
Exactly where I told you
not to be--
on a shuttlecraft.
I have to see the Doctor.
Well, that'd be nice
if he were still around.
( moans )
I told you,
you were in no condition
to come on a supply mission,
but did you listen to me?
( cries out )
( panting )
I can see the toes...
( grunting )
It's coming...
Kes...
Oh, it's a girl.
( baby crying )
Oh...
Linnis.
Shh...
She's beautiful.
Yes, she is.
Yes, just like
her mother.
Tom, listen.
I love you, Kes.
We need to talk.
( beeping )
Just a minute.
But...
What is it?
Voyager's under attack.
( tense dramatic
score playing )
Congratulations.
Thanks.
But it looks like the
celebration'll have to wait.
I'll get Kes and the baby
to the Mess Hall.
Captain Chakotay wants you
to go to the weapons array
and modulate
the targeting scanners
to a parametric
frequency.
He's going to try
to knock out
the chroniton
torpedo launchers
before they're fired.
Chroniton torpedoes--
the "Year of Hell."
What?
You told me that the crew
referred to this time
as the "Year of Hell."
When did I tell
you that?
It's a long story.
( baby crying )
You'll have to
tell me later.
I've got to get to
the weapons array.
Neelix, get her
to lie down, will you?
Neelix, listen
very carefully.
There's something important
I have to tell you.
( baby crying )
Neelix told us what's been
happening to you, Kes.
How are you holding up?
We're both fine.
It's quite
a story.
Just before the last jump,
we were close to a solution.
The Doctor was working on...
The Doctor?
Well, it's good to know
we'll eventually
get him back on line.
"Eventually"
may be too late.
We've got
to help Kes now.
We discovered that what's
been happening to me
is related
to the chroniton poisoning
I suffered during
a Krenim attack.
We have to determine
the exact temporal variance
of the torpedo, so that we...
The main computer's
been off-line for weeks.
Even if the sensor logs
contain that information,
we can't access them.
You have to put me in the
bio-temporal containment field.
I know it didn't work last time,
but with a few modifications...
We've only got life-support
on three out of 14 decks.
And we've had to divert
all remaining power
to knock out the Krenim's
torpedo launchers.
We don't even have
a Sick Bay anymore,
much less the resources
to create a bio-
containment field.
I'm sorry.
We've got to do
something to help her.
I'm open to
suggestions.
I'm cold.
I'll get you a blanket.
No. You don't
understand.
I'm abou...
I'm about...
( steel drum music playing )
Tom...
Hey, Kes.
Some party, huh?
I have to talk to you.
TORRES:
Tom...
I'm sorry I'm late.
You must be B'Elanna.
( all laugh )
Well, the last time
I checked.
Is something wrong?
Actually...
there is something wrong.
JANEWAY:
Red Alert.
All hands
to battle stations.
( grunts )
Tuvok, fire phasers.
Acknowledged.
Who the hell are they?
KES:
They're called
the Krenim.
How do you know that?
Captain Janeway?
What is it, Kes?
What do you know
about them?
Shields down to 39 percent,
Captain.
I don't understand
how these torpedoes
are ripping right through
our shields.
Evasive maneuvers,
Mr. Paris.
B'Elanna, can we reroute power
to the forward shields?
TORRES:
I'm already trying.
Captain, these torpedoes
are chroniton-based.
They're passing through
our shields
because they're in a state
of temporal flux.
( yelling )
( alarm blaring;
agitated voices )
They're dead.
( dramatic theme playing )
B'Elanna!
Hull breach on Deck 7.
We're losing life-support.
Evacuate the deck.
Tom, I need you at the conn.
Aye, sir.
Commander, they're arming
their torpedo
launchers again.
We cannot sustain
another direct hit.
Kes, you seem to know
something about these weapons.
Do you have any idea
how we can stop them?
I'm not sure, but I think
it has something to do
with remodulating
the targeting scanners.
KIM:
That could work.
If we remodulate the scanners
to a parametric frequency,
we might be able to destroy
the torpedo launchers
before they fire.
Mr. Tuvok, you heard the man.
Tom, bring us about.
Ready, Commander.
Fire!
CHAKOTAY:
Do you have a casualty report?
KIM: Including Captain Janeway
and B'Elanna, we lost 11 people.
What about the ship?
Starboard shield generators
and warp drive are off-line,
and power is down
on Decks 4 through 12.
Make Deck 5 your priority.
We've got to get
Sick Bay up and running again.
Aye, sir.
Kes, as far as what you say
is happening to you...
I understand
that my condition
can't be a priority now.
Tom, I'm going to
need you to stay here
and help treat
these people.
When this is over,
we're all going to have
a lot of grieving to do.
How are you doing?
Tom?
I know it doesn't
seem possible now,
but you're going
to be all right.
I wish I could believe you.
You can.
Thanks.
Kes, we've got
radiation leakage
coming from one of the Krenim
torpedo fragments.
People are starting
to complain of nausea.
Chroniton radiation.
This is it.
I'm infected.
Where's the radiation
coming from?
It's lodged in a Jefferies
tube on Deck 11, Section 2.
I've got to get down there.
You can't, the entire
deck is sealed off.
I have to find the exact
temporal variance
of that torpedo.
You can't go near that thing.
You'll be burned to a crisp.
I know what I'm doing.
You stay here and help
Tom, all right?
Yes, but...
( alarm blaring )
( beeping )
( clears throat )
( coughing )
Kes, how are you coming
with those
analgesic compounds?
Doctor, you've lost
your hair.
I beg your pardon?
It's a long story.
The important thing is,
the temporal variance
of the chroniton torpedo
was 1.47 microseconds.
As far as I can determine,
I've now jumped a total
of six years into my past.
Do you have any theory
as to the cause of these jumps?
According to Kes,
she and the rest of the crew
will be infected
by chroniton radiation
approximately 11 months
from now.
Everyone will be inoculated
and the effects
will appear to vanish.
However, some five years later,
when I attempt an experimental--
and I might add,
ingenious procedure
to extend her life-span--
the bio-temporal field
I expose her to will trigger
dormant chroniton particles,
taking Kes out of temporal sync
and causing her to begin her
backward journey through time.
In all my years
in Starfleet,
I've never come across
a phenomenon quite like this.
Kes has been able to provide us
with the precise temporal
variance of the torpedo
which infected her.
Since Kes is moving
backward in time, she's
already been infected
by the radiation poisoning.
If we can set up
a bio-temporal chamber
and expose her
to a precisely modulated field
of antichroniton particles, we
feel this may purge her system
and bring her back in temporal
sync with the rest of us.
Well, we better get moving.
For all we know, Kes's
next jump will take her
back to a time when
we're not here to help her.
Captain, there's something else
I have to tell you.
In about six months,
you're going to enter
a region of space controlled
by a race called the Krenim.
You must avoid them
at all costs.
Tell me more.
TORRES:
I'm ready to bring
the chamber online.
Synaptic relays are operational.
How are her vital signs?
Pulse normal,
body temperature 14 degrees.
Chroniton level
at 79 roentgens.
Go ahead and activate
the chamber, Lieutenant.
Increase the bio-temporal
field stress.
Bringing field stress
to 25 kilodynes.
All right, let's try
the antichronitons.
Whenever
you're ready, Doc.
Initiating antichroniton burst.
Ten MEVs, five second pulse.
Pulse steady.
Body temperature at 14.2 degrees
and rising.
JANEWAY:
What about her
chroniton count?
Chroniton count...
is 71 roentgens
and dropping.
It's working.
DOCTOR:
Lieutenant Torres,
increase the field
strength to 30 kilodynes.
Right.
Initiating
another burst.
15 MEVs, five
second pulse.
Body temperature, 14.9 degrees.
Chroniton count, 68 roentgens...
Sixty...
Fifty-seven...
Fifty-two...
NEELIX:
You need a cook.
You haven't lived until
you've tasted my angla'bosque.
It will be my job
to anticipate your needs
before you know
you have them.
Not again.
And I anticipate
your first need will be me.
I'm sorry.
I know this is going to
sound strange to you both,
but I don't belong here.
But we discussed this.
You don't understand.
I'm traveling backwards
in time, getting younger.
We have to lower
my chroniton levels.
You've got to get me
into the bio-temporal
chamber right away.
I-I'm sorry, Captain.
I-I didn't quite
anticipate this.
Listen to me, please.
Sweeting, try to calm down.
I assure you, Captain,
she's never behaved
this way before.
Hold on a minute,
Mr. Neelix.
Kes, why don't you
start over slowly?
It begins about eight years
in the future
when I'm about to die...
No!
MALE:
Time for dinner.
What's wrong, Kes?
Who are you?
What is this place?
We don't have
time to play
our guessing game
right now, Kes.
You know how your mother gets
when we're late to the table.
You're my father.
That's right, and you're
my favorite daughter,
but don't tell anyone.
Listen to me.
Something terrible's
been happening to me.
What's wrong?
There might not be much time,
so I've got to explain quickly.
Please try to believe me.
I've been living aboard
a starship called Voyager.
A starship... I see.
So now it's not only the surface
you're dreaming about exploring.
Listen to me.
I did go to the surface,
or, rather, I will go there,
and the people aboard the ship,
they're going to rescue me
from the Kazon
and take me
with them.
Why don't you
finish telling me
about your adventures
after dinner?
No! There's no time.
You've got to believe me.
One moment, I was
this old woman,
and then,
and then...
Kes, we're late.
Father, please.
( groaning )
( yelling in pain )
I can see the toes!
It's coming, Martis.
( yelling in pain )
It's a girl.
( baby wailing )
Oh!
Oh, Kes!
Oh...
( heartbeat thudding )
It's a girl.
( baby wailing )
Oh!
Oh, she's so...
She's so beautiful.
Kes!
Oh...
I think one day,
she'll see the sun.
( gurgling )
( tricorder beeping )
51 roentgens.
Forty-six...
Thirty-four.
Another antichroniton burst--
20 MEVs.
Right.
Levels are continuing to drop.
Pulse normal.
Body temperature steady
at 16.3 degrees.
( tricorder beeping )
Chroniton levels
are at zero roentgens.
Welcome back, Kes.
What's the date?
How old am I?
The same age you were
when we put you into
the bio-temporal chamber--
a healthy three years
and two months.
And due to an extraordinary
display of medical heroics,
you're back in temporal sync
with the rest of us.
So, I'm going to become
a security officer.
How about that?
Fortunately,
Mr. Neelix,
what Kes has
been describing
is merely
one possible future.
On each occasion
that she jumped
to a previous time,
her subsequent actions
most likely altered the future
from that moment on.
Good point, Tuvok.
Maybe I'll turn out to be
Chief Security Officer.
KIM:
So, Kes...
have you regained all
your memories of the past?
I remember last month's
supply of replicator rations
that you borrowed
that you owe me...
if that's
what you're asking.
Don't worry.
I haven't forgotten.
I realize
it's only hypothetical,
but still,
I'd be curious to know
what sorts
of medical breakthroughs
I'm going to make
in this possible future.
It's not as if
I've seen everything
that's going to happen
over the next six years.
I only remember
short periods
I experienced
between jumps.
Even so,
I bet you found out
some pretty
interesting things.
Yeah, Kes.
Tell us what you know.
CHAKOTAY:
Careful, Tom.
You may find out
that you leave Voyager
only to join a monastery.
( laughter )
Hey, give him
a little credit.
I'll bet he gets married
and has a family.
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
Are you telling?
Well,
as Tuvok said,
I've only seen pieces
of one possible future.
PARIS:
You know what?
Don't tell me.
I don't want to know.
I like a little
mystery in my life.
JANEWAY:
Tom's right.
I think we should all leave
the future to the future.
While I agree it would
not be wise for Kes
to make all of
her experiences public,
a report on
anything she knows
about these Krenim
might be useful.
I'll get started right away.
JANEWAY:
Hang on a minute.
I didn't mean now.
Stay and enjoy your party.
If there's one thing this
experience has taught me,
it's that there's
no time like the present.
( all scoff )
( light
dramatic music playing )
( dramatic
theme music playing )