WOMAN:
Jeffrey... Belle...
We're going to be late
if you don't hurry.
Come on, now.
Line up next to the door,
children.
Your father's ready
to leave for work.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
All right.
Show me your fingernails.
Very nicely done.
Are your shoes polished?
Perfect.
I'm very pleased, children
and I'm sure
your father will be, too.
I want to be first
to say good-bye to Daddy.
Jeffrey always goes first.
You were
first yesterday.
Now, children, little birds
in their nest get along.
You're right,
mother.
I'm sorry, Belle.
You can go first.
No, it's really your turn.
I did go first yesterday.
( door closes )
Here he comes!
All right, now.
Bright, happy faces.
The coffee was quite good
this morning.
I'm so glad you like it.
I replicated a new blend
from Paksor Three.
I'll be home
at the usual time.
Now don't let them
over work you.
You should save yourself
for the important things.
Others can do
the busy work.
I couldn't agree more.
I hope you have a good day,
father.
I'll have my homework finished
by the time you get back.
I'll look forward
to reviewing it, Jeffrey.
And is my little angel going
to get an "A" on
her history exam today?
Of course I will, daddy.
And can we do
some algebra problems
when you get home?
Gladly.
And don't forget--
your going to ask
some of your friends from work
to have dinner with us.
I'd like to meet them.
I haven't forgotten.
Well...
Good-bye, all.
Good-bye, Daddy.
How's the new
holo-family, doctor?
They're everything
I could've hoped for.
Captain's log, stardate
50836.2.
We've had
long-range communications
with a seemingly friendly race
known as the Vostigye.
We'll be rendezvousing
within the hour
at one of their space stations.
Ensign Kim, perhaps you could
direct your attention
to the sensors
and tell us if we're nearing
the Vostigye
space station.
We should be getting close.
That's funny.
I'm not detecting it.
You've checked
the coordinates they sent us?
Yes, and... hold on.
Now I'm
getting something.
It's... debris.
Debris?
TUVOK:
Confirmed.
I am reading
a debris field encompassing
nearly 80 cubic kilometers.
What's the composition
of the debris?
Boronite, sarium,
carbon 60 composites.
Sounds like it could've
been a space station.
On screen.
What happened to it?
Something ripped it apart, and
from the energy decay readings,
I'd say it was no more
than an hour ago.
I'm not picking up any life
signs, captain.
There don't
appear to be any survivors.
There were 60 Vostigye
scientists on that station.
I don't read any recognizable
weapons signatures.
Maybe somebody in this part
of space has weapons
that don't leave
a traditional signature.
I'd like to know who they are
and why they'd annihilate
a science station.
Maybe we can find out, captain.
There's a strange pattern
that seems to be emanating
from subspace.
Looks like some kind
of plasma particles.
I've got it, too.
It's like a...
a wake leading away
from the debris field.
From a ship?
I can't tell.
Set a course
to follow it, Tom.
Yes, Ma'am.
Optical processors,
imaging array--
they all check out, doctor.
You are in perfect health.
I'm sure I could've
told you that.
Yes, I'm sure you could have.
But, with all the tinkering
you've been doing
with your program lately
I'd feel better giving
you these
little tune-ups
on a regular basis.
The tinkering you speak
of has been for the sole purpose
of improving my performance
as a physician.
I can hardly be
faulted for that.
I'm not faulting you for
your intentions, doctor.
I think it's rather commendable
that you want
to improve yourself.
That's why I've
created a family.
A family?
I've listened
to enough patients
talk about their
families to realize
how meaningful they are
to biological beings.
For better or worse, yes.
The doctor has created
a holographic wife and two
children, so he can experience
family life for himself.
Interesting.
And how's it going so far?
Splendidly.
From what I heard
I thought it
would be difficult
but I'm enjoying
the experience.
You are?
Funny. I never thought
of you as a family man, Doc.
I'd like to meet them.
As a matter of fact,
the "little woman" has been
asking me to bring some of
my colleagues home for dinner.
Perhaps you and Kes would
care to join us tonight?
Charlene is
a wonderful cook.
I'd like to meet them, too.
Well, Doc, tell your wife
to haul out the good china.
You're having company.
Ah.
Please, have some more
wild mushroom pilaf, B'elanna.
Uh, thanks. I've had
two helpings already.
It's delicious.
I took a course
in continental cuisine
so I could replicate interesting
meals for Kenneth.
Kenneth?
My husband.
What do you call him?
Oh, we call him Doctor.
Oh, of course.
Anyway, he works terribly hard
and he's under
such great stress.
I want this home
to be his sanctuary the place
he can come and have all
the cares of the day disappear.
How nice for him.
My daddy is
a very important man.
He's the best doctor
there ever was
and he saves people's lives
all the time.
A slight exaggeration.
It is not! You said...
Belle, eat
your dinner.
They're well aware
of my talents.
Jeffrey, why don't
you tell our guests
about your new project
at school.
I've designed
a micro-filter input
which will make it possible
to cleanse blood
of harmful microorganisms
too small to stimulate
an immune response.
Jeffrey is extremely bright.
He's in the accelerated physical
sciences program at school.
A regular chip off
the old block, right?
And don't forget
about our little belle.
She's already studying
algebra and trigonometry,
and she's quite
the budding athlete.
You must be very proud
of your family, doctor.
Oh.
Well, we're proud of him, too.
In fact, we think we have
just about the most wonderful
husband and father
in the quadrant, don't we?
Computer, freeze program.
KIDS:
Yes, we do--
Lieutenant, what are you doing?
I am stopping this before
my blood sugar levels overload.
Doctor...
Yes?
If you think this is giving you
an accurate impression
of being in a family
you are sadly mistaken.
I don't understand.
They're kind of perfect.
They are ridiculously perfect.
No one has
a family like this.
This is a fantasy.
You're not going
to learn anything
from being with these...
lollipops.
I provided the computer
with my requirements
for a mate and children.
If I were to
choose a real wife
my taste would
be the same--
Intelligence, education,
organizational skills...
There is nothing wrong
with your premise, doctor.
It just needs
a little tweaking
to bring it
closer to real life.
I can help...
if you'd like.
Captain, the particle wake
we've been following
is beginning to thin out.
Is there any indication
what caused it?
I am detecting no ships,
no structures
no weapons signatures.
Wait a minute.
Something.
I see it, too.
A subspace disruption.
What's causing it?
Can't tell, but it's
getting more intense.
Shields up. Red alert.
Tom, back us off.
Something's coming out
of subspace.
JANEWAY:
Tom, move us away!
I don't have engines!
Propulsion is off line.
So is navigational control.
Bridge to Engineering--
we need power.
B'ELANNA:
I'm on it, Captain.
The anomaly
is bearing down on us,
heading 0-4-7, mark 1-9.
Brace for impact.
KIM:
It hit our
starboard shields!
There's damage on deck three.
Ready weapons.
We're going to disperse it.
Phasers on line...
CHAKOTAY:
Wait a minute.
I'm not afraid to say it.
I've never seen anything
like that before.
Damage report.
TUVOK:
20% loss of
the starboard dorsal shields
and minor buckling
of the hull on deck three.
No indication of casualties.
PARIS:
We've got propulsion
systems back online
I think I can put some distance
between us
and whatever that was.
Maybe we don't want to.
We've just witnessed
a phenomenon
none of us
has ever heard of before
much less experienced.
On a purely scientific level
I think we owe it
to ourselves
to investigate.
I'm looking at the telemetry
we collected.
It was an astral eddy
that seems to have formed
at the confluence
of space and subspace.
KIM:
It was highly charged
with plasma.
That explains the particle wake.
If we could harness
some of that energy
we could go off replicator
rations for a while.
Captain, we don't have any idea
what caused that phenomenon
or what made it dissipate.
So how do we investigate it
if it's gone?
I suspect there are conditions
in this part of space
that lend themselves to
the formation of those eddies.
Set sensors for continuous
scans of subspace.
Maybe we can anticipate
the next one.
DOCTOR:
I thought for a long time about
what Lieutenant Torres said
and I finally concluded
she was right.
If I'm going to have
the experience of a family
it should be as
authentic as possible.
What changes have you asked
her to make in the program?
Oh, she's already made them.
She simply added some randomized
behavioral algorithms
to the program
I constructed.
How will that
affect your family?
Events will simply unfold
as a natural evolution
of probabilities
within the program.
But there's no way to
predict what those might be.
That could mean
a few surprises.
Are you sure you're
ready for this?
My database contains
everything there is to know
about pediatric care
and childhood development.
I can't imagine a parenting
problem I couldn't handle.
Your wife
will have changed, too.
Well, I have had some experience
with romantic relationships.
I don't anticipate
any problems there.
Sounds like you have
it all worked out.
When do you plan on meeting
this new, improved family?
Right now.
I'm due home for dinner.
Computer, initiate Doctor's
family program beta-rho
and transfer the E.M.H.
to holodeck two.
Hello! I'm...
Home.
CHARLENE:
There you are.
I thought
you'd never get here.
It was a busy day.
I was quite challenged
by the task of preparing
a DNA probe to test ensign
parson's glial cells.
It seems he has
a microbial infection.
Rather unusual.
Tell me about it
when I get home.
I'm late already.
Late?
It's Wednesday,
remember?
I'm speaking
at the Bolian embassy.
Ah, right.
Is dinner ready?
It's your night
to cook.
BELLE:
Mom, I can't find
my ion mallet!
If you cleaned your room,
you'd have better luck!
( pounding, shrieking
music playing )
What is that noise?
I've had to listen
to it all day.
Maybe you can do
something about it.
Daddy!
You've got to help me!
I'll be late for practice.
Coach Morgan will be furious
if I'm late again.
If you put your mallet
in your closet
when you were done with
it you'd know where it was.
I know that, Daddy!
Ugh! Tell Jeffrey
to turn that off!
It makes my eyes hurt!
Mine, too.
Jeffrey!
What?
What is that music?
Klingon.
Well, turn it down! You can't do
your homework with that noise.
BELLE:
Daddy, I can't find my mallet!
I know that, Belle.
The coach will send me
down to the second team!
Well, perhaps that will
teach you a lesson.
You don't
understand anything!
Belle, you have to realize...
( banging at door )
Where's Jeffrey?
Who are you?
Friends.
Do you have names?
Larg.
K'kath.
Well, Larg, K'kath,
you'll have to come back later.
Jeffrey's doing his homework.
LARG:
He invited us!
BELLE:
Daddy! I need my ion mallet!
I...!
Just a minute.
I'm sorry, but Jeffrey
can't see friends
until he has finished
his homework.
Dad... I asked them to come.
Daddy!
Jeffrey, this is unacceptable.
It'll only take a minute.
We have some business
we have to do.
Business?
Yighos pa'wijdaq.
Qay'be'.
Where's my mallet?
I need it now!
Young man!
You're mean! You don't
love me as much as mommy does
she'd help me find
my mallet!
I want mommy!
( door slams )
( crying )
( pan contents sizzling )
Nothing striking your fancy,
lieutenant?
Isn't this
the fourth day in a row
we've had
the same casserole?
Pleeka rinds and grub meal--
very tasty,
if I do say so myself.
Well, you did a great job
with it, no question.
It'd just be nice
to have a little variety.
Well, you're perfectly free
to use the replicators.
Um, I'm out of rations.
Then...
enjoy the casserole.
A beautiful woman should
never have to eat alone.
What are you reading?
It's nothing important.
Ah.
Women Warriors
at the River of Blood?
It's just... escapist reading.
Ah.
"Rorg turned his fierce eye
upon her
"and M'nea felt her heart
begin to quicken
"even as her hand
went to her dagger.
"she had intended to plunge
it into his throat
but something about him
made her hesitate."
B'elanna, is this
a Klingon romance novel?
The Klingons do have what you
might call a romantic side.
It's a bit more
vigorous than most.
I think I'll read it.
Maybe it'll give me some ideas
about how
to make your heart quicken.
It's not a technical
manual, Tom.
Well, that depends on what
you mean by "technical."
To an engineer, that means...
"specializing
in particular systems."
I think that
definition works.
Well, I can't promise I won't
put a dagger in your throat.
Have you heard about
the Doctor's new family?
How's it going?
I think he was a little
overwhelmed at first
but I have to give
him credit.
He's sticking with it.
It's hard to imagine
the doctor with children.
( both chuckling )
JANEWAY:
Senior staff to
the bridge immediately.
Tom, I want to send
a probe into that anomaly.
Can you hold position
close enough
for us to get
accurate telemetry?
I can try.
CHAKOTAY:
Be ready to move
away quickly
if it starts moving toward us.
Sorry about that.
Just trying to find a way to
ride the gravitron waves
it's throwing off.
There.
That's a little better.
We're in as good a position
as we're going to be.
Tuvok?
The probe has been launched.
Actually,
this is kind of fun.
Speak for yourself.
KIM:
We're starting
to receive telemetry.
Captain, this is
one weird disturbance.
I'm reading
a temperature gradient
of nine million kelvins,
massive discharges
of plasmatic energy,
and there's a perfectly
calm eye at the center.
TUVOK:
Apparently, some
of the matter inside it
is being exchanged
between space and subspace.
What about the plasma?
Is there any way
we can transfer
some of it to Voyager?
I don't see how.
We can't transport
with this kind
of turbulence.
Maybe we could try a...
we lost it.
Where's the probe?
It's disappeared.
It's still transmitting
but there's a lot
of interference.
I'm detecting some kind
of unstable interfold layer
not in space
or subspace.
It could be where
the eddies originate
and where the probe is now.
We've got another particle wake.
Since we can't get plasma
directly from the eddies,
maybe we could collect
some from their wakes.
The bussard collectors
could be modified
to gather plasma particles.
We could do that,
but Voyager's energy emissions
are so high they'd corrupt the
particles.
I'm not sure the plasma
would be much use to us.
PARIS:
What if I took
a shuttle out?
The energy emissions
would be a lot lower.
That sounds like
it's worth a try.
Well, you'd be exposing yourself
to radiation poisoning.
Check with the doctor. Maybe
he can give you some protection.
Yes, ma'am. I'll head
to the shuttlebay
as soon as I'm done.
I've given you a combination
of hyronalin and lectrazine.
That should give you
temporary protection.
But I can't guarantee
its duration.
That's all right, doc.
I don't think I'll be
out there too long.
If I know you, you'll
push it to the limit.
You enjoy flirting
with danger.
You know me too well.
You were undoubtedly
one of those children
who had to climb
the highest tree...
scale the tallest cliff.
That was me.
I can only imagine what you must
have put your parents through.
How's the family, Doc?
I hear they're
a real handful.
Indeed. However, I have
analyzed the situation
and come up with a solution.
There should be
no more problems.
You make it sound like
you're treating a sick patient.
I'm not sure you can
diagnose and cure a family.
We'll see.
You're in fine physical
shape, lieutenant.
You may go ahead and engage
in this reckless activity.
Thanks, Doc.
Where's Jeffrey?!
He's coming.
I asked everyone to be here
at 1600 hours, precisely.
Jeffrey was asleep.
Asleep? In the middle
of the afternoon?
( sighing )
Is this true?
Were you asleep?
Are you sick?
I had a late night.
That's one of the matters
I want to discuss.
Thank you all for coming.
I thought it would be good
to have a family meeting.
In fact, I'd like to
do this on a regular basis.
That's something
to look forward to.
If you have something
to say, Jeffrey
say it so everyone can hear.
Nothing.
I've been feeling
that this family
is beginning to spin
out of control.
As husband and father
I believe it is my duty
to set some parameters.
It's part of good parenting.
What are parameters?
Limits. Boundaries.
To that end,
I have drawn up
a revised family schedule and
a list of rules and regulations.
I'd like you all
to study them carefully.
You've rearranged
my lecture nights!
I had to do that in order
to make everything work.
Everybody has had
to make some sacrifices.
Daddy! You changed
parisses' squares
from Monday-Wednesday-Friday
to Tuesday-Thursday-Saturday!
Mm-hmm--that puts me
on the second team!
I'm good enough to be
on the first team!
You shouldn't be
on the first team.
You're not old enough.
As I said Belle, we must
all make sacrifices.
What sacrifices did you make?
I will make dinner on the nights
your mother lectures.
You do that anyway.
That's not a sacrifice.
What's this mean
about no Klingon friends?!
Exactly that.
They're a bad influence on you.
They're prone to violence, they
keep you out till all hours.
Why don't you find
some nice Vulcan friends?
You can't just decide
who my friends will be!
CHARLENE:
Hold on.
Kenneth, that may be
a bit unreasonable.
Charlene?
( whispering ):
You know very well
how important it is
to keep a united front.
I expect you to support
me in these decisions.
Well, if that's
what you expect
then maybe you should
have asked my opinion
before you started
unilaterally deciding things.
I'm not one of
the children, after all.
I believe I should
have some say
in just what rules and
regulations are established!
And I think it's unfair
for you to tell Jeffrey
what friends he can
and cannot have.
Right! This whole meeting
is a Vulky idea!
And you can have it without me.
Jeffrey, you were
not excused!
You've upset him.
Let him go.
I don't want to argue this
in front of the children.
We'll discuss it later.
You really made a mess
of things didn't you, daddy?
Apparently so.
Although, I must admit, I fail
to understand the reaction.
I... I'm just trying to help the
family function better.
How does it make the family
function better
if I go to parisses' squares
Tuesday, Thursday and Saturday?
Belle, you've been playing
with children
two and three years older
than you.
That's much
too dangerous.
But that's what's
fun about it.
( sighing )
You're not old enough
to realize
how hazardous that game can be.
It's up to me to keep you safe.
I...
I'm just trying
to be a good father.
If it'll help, Daddy,
I'll be on the second team.
Thank you, Belle.
That's very grown-up of you.
And I think you're
a very good father.
Why... thank you.
I love you, daddy...
even if you did
make a mess of things.
JANEWAY:
Voyager to
shuttlecraft Cochran.
Do you read?
Loud and clear captain.
I'm about 3,000 kilometers
from the eddy.
As soon as it dissipates
I'll head for the particle wave.
If this one follows
the pattern of the others
it should begin to collapse
within a few seconds.
That's good.
I'm beginning to wish
I hadn't had
that second helping
of French toast this morning.
KIM:
Captain, the eddy
is starting to dissipate.
Stand by, Tom.
I'm ready.
I'm in position, captain.
Activating
the bussard collectors.
It's working.
This may save us from Neelix's
pleeka rind casserole
after all.
We'll all thank you
for that.
KIM:
Captain, subspace disruption.
Is another eddy forming?
It looks that way.
Tom, get out of there now.
I'm going.
Harry, can you beam him out?
KIM:
Transporters are off line.
I'm working on them.
Tom, are you there?
It's pulling me in!
I don't have enough power!
Where are the transporters?
I can't access them!
The shuttle's being drawn
inside the eddy.
Janeway to Paris,
Do you read me?
Captain, the astral eddy
is beginning to dissipate.
Harry,
when the probe disappeared,
it kept transmitting.
What about Tom's shuttle?
We're getting
a lot of interference.
I can't tell if
it's a transmission or not.
See if you can clean it up.
I've adjusted the encoding
filter. Try it now.
Voyager to Tom Paris.
Can you hear us? Respond.
Calibrate
to a theta band frequency.
Maybe that'll help.
PARIS:
I can't hear you, Captain.
There's a lot
of plasma interference.
I can't clean it up.
Say again, Tom.
You're breaking up.
Adjust your transceiver
lock and try again.
I can hear you.
That better?
Yes, a little.
Where are you?
Captain,
I wish I could tell you.
( sighing )
Doctor?
Hmm?
Can I help you
with something?
Oh, no, no.
Uh. Perhaps.
I've been trying to do
an immunogenicity analysis
on Ensign Parson's
cell culture
and I can't seem to get
the measurements right.
I'd be happy
to give it a try.
Thank you.
I'd be grateful.
Actually,
I've been having
a few problems at home.
I can't seem to stop
thinking about them.
Well, there's nothing
important going on here.
Why don't you
take the afternoon off
and spend some time
with your family?
I'm not sure
they'd appreciate it.
Doctor,
you can't just ignore them.
Computer, initiate Doctor's
family program beta-rho
and transfer the E.M.H.
to holodeck two.
LARG:
Be certain everything
is done in exactly...
Dad, what are you doing here?
I live here, Jeffrey,
in case you've forgotten.
I mean... you're home early.
Am I interrupting something?
Uh... no, no.
Just talking with my friends.
I'd like to get
to know your friends.
Larg, K'kath,
please sit down.
What is that?
What?
You're holding something.
This?
Yes. What is it?
It's a knife.
What does it look like?
Why do you boys have a knife?
A D'k Tahg knife
is an important part
of our culture.
Every Klingon is given one
in preparation for
his rite of ascension.
Hmm.
I happen to know something
about Klingon rituals
and I believe this is actually
a dagger of Kut'luch.
Isn't it?
Well?
Yes.
This dagger is used
in a ritual of violence.
A first bloodletting
in preparation
for becoming a warrior.
Who's supposed to use this?
Well?
Is one of you preparing
for the Kut'luch ceremony?
I'm waiting for an answer!
Dad, you're making something
out of nothing.
I don't think so.
I'm going to have
to ask you boys to leave.
JEFFREY:
Dad...
And don't bring a weapon
into this house again.
I told you,
humans are weak... cowardly.
Call me later.
( door slams )
Now look what you've done!
You've ruined it!
What, exactly, have I ruined?
Nothing! Never mind!
You were going to use that
knife, weren't you?!
Did they talk you into some
kind of ritual violence?
They didn't talk
me into anything.
I asked them.
It's an honor to get to
perform the Kut'luch.
They don't just
let anybody do it.
They trusted me
and now you've made me
look like... like a human.
You were going to attack
someone, draw blood,
just so you could appear daring
in the eyes of your friends?!
I was doing it
to become honorable--
something that you
wouldn't understand.
Jeffrey, how can
I make you understand
that what you were
going to do is wrong?
It isn't wrong!
It's just the custom
of another culture.
Who are you to say there's
something wrong about it?
I am your father,
and I expect you to be guided
by my ethical standards.
Well, I'm not going to be.
Your standards
are human standards.
They're weak and inferior.
Klingon ideals are much nobler
and they are the ones
I'm going to follow.
If you expect to live
in this household
you will abide by the rules.
If that's
the way you want it
then I won't live here.
Jeffrey...
think about this.
Oh, I've thought about it.
I'm going to become a warrior,
and I can't do that
if I'm being led around on a
leash by some bloodless patahk.
( door shuts )
( chime ringing )
Kenneth?
What is it? What's happened?
It's Belle.
There's been an accident.
How is she?
Dr. Finley and I operated
on her for three hours.
We've tried everything.
We shut down
one hemorrhage
and another starts.
I don't understand.
She just hit her head
on the corner of the court.
How could that have
injured her so badly?
She suffered severe
cranial trauma.
It's compromised her brain stem
and motor cortex.
No matter how we try
to control
the vascular injuries
blood clots keep forming.
The hemorrhaging is...
intractable.
Then what do you do?
What's the treatment?
Unfortunately...
the brain is still a...
a somewhat
mysterious organ.
What does that mean?
What's going to happen to her?
There's nothing
more to be done.
Nothing medical, anyway.
Oh, but there has to be.
Kenneth, you can do something.
You have to.
You can't just let her...
No.
No, I won't accept it.
I'm going to talk
to Dr. Finley.
Belle...
BELLE:
Daddy?
Yes?
I'm here.
Everything's all blurry.
What's the matter?
You took a tumble...
hit your head.
It doesn't hurt.
No, because
we gave you some medicine.
Is that why
I can't feel my legs?
Yes.
What's going to happen?
When will I be able
to see again?
Computer, end program.
KES: Oh, you're back.
Yes.
Did you find the culture I did
on Ensign Parson's glial cells?
I did, thank you.
Good job.
How's the family?
I suppose they're fine.
I've actually finished
the program.
Finished? Already?
Well, I'd gotten what
I needed from the experience.
It was thoroughly pleasurable,
of course,
but to continue
would be a waste of time.
I was hoping
to visit them again.
I really enjoyed
our dinner together.
Well, if I ever create
a new family,
I'll be sure to invite you.
B'ELANNA:
The communications bandwidth
is as wide as I can get it.
Janeway to Paris.
How's the transmission now?
Loud and clear, Captain.
I've been analyzing
the shuttle's sensor readings,
and as nearly as I can figure,
I'm in the interfold layer
that we talked about--
somewhere between space
and subspace.
That's why we can't find
you on any of our scans.
Harry was right.
This looks like
the spawning ground
for the astral eddies.
There are thousands
of baby ones in here.
That's very interesting, Tom,
but it doesn't address
the problem
of how to get you out of there.
Well, I've been giving that some
careful thought, Captain,
and it seems to me
the only way to get out
is the same way that I got in.
Inside one of the eddies?
Exactly.
I've been watching one.
It seems about ready
to erupt into normal space.
If I can position the shuttle
on its leading edge
I should be able
to ride it back.
If I had another idea,
I'd suggest it, but I don't.
It's your call, Tom.
I don't see
that there's much choice.
So far so good, captain.
I'm almost inside the eye.
I think this one
is just about big enough
to enter normal space.
Here it comes.
Captain?
Yes, Tom.
I think you should get Voyager
away from here .
What's wrong?
This one's turning out
to be a whopper.
The biggest one
we've seen by far.
I don't think you should put
the ship in danger.
I'm not leaving, tom.
We've got to stay in close
if we're going to beam you out.
The eddy is moving toward us
at a velocity of 300 kilometers
per second.
JANEWAY:
Chakotay, take the conn.
Keep us ahead of it, but stay
within transporter range.
Right.
I'm going to try
to get out of this.
( groans )
( panting )
Harry, can you
get a lock on him?
Not yet! Everything's too
unstable.
Tom, how much longer
before you clear the eddy?
It had better be soon.
The hull is beginning to buckle.
I've got the shuttle on sensors.
The hull is breaching!
Harry, can you
get a lock on him yet?
I'm trying! Hang on!
Got it!
The shuttle's aboard, Captain.
One life sign.
He's injured.
Beam him to sick bay. Chakotay,
move us away.
Yes, Ma'am.
DOCTOR:
Your hard head has protected
you again, lieutenant.
There was only
a mild concussion.
It was worth it, though.
That was one wild ride.
I'm sure it was.
And it's a wonder
you're not dead.
People like you who court danger
should be thrown into the brig.
Doc...
You never think
of the consequences
of your actions,
the effect they
might have on others.
Oh, no, live for the moment
take risks you shouldn't...
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
I... it's my family.
My daughter Belle
had an accident.
She's a child who tends
to take risks.
She's going to die.
I'm so sorry.
I'll be all right.
I shut down the program.
I'm not going back.
Maybe you should think
about that, Doc.
I couldn't begin...
to face it.
It was too difficult.
I guess all of us
would avoid
that kind of pain
if we could...
but most people
don't have that choice.
Well, fortunately, I do.
Is it so fortunate?
You created that program
so you could experience
what it's like
to have a family
the good times and the bad.
You can't have one
without the other.
I fail to see why not.
Well, think about what's
happened to us here on Voyager.
Everyone left people behind,
and everyone suffered a loss
but look how it's brought
us all closer together.
We've found support here,
and friendship,
and we've become a family
in part because
of the pain we shared.
If you turn your back
on this program
you'll always be stuck
at this point.
You'll never have the chance
to say good-bye to your daughter
or to be there
for your wife and son
when they need you
and you'll be
cheating yourself
of the chance to have
their love and support.
In the long run,
you'll miss the whole point
of what it means
to have a family.
Computer, continue Doctor's
family program beta-rho
from the last point
of deactivation.
Daddy...
what's going
to happen to me?
When will I be able
to see again?
I'm not sure.
You're a very sick girl.
Am I going to die?
You're...
you're too sick to get better.
So, I'm going to die.
Yes.
If you stay with me...
I won't be afraid.
I'll stay right here.
I promise.
Dad...
Here you go, shorty.
It's your blanket.
We're here, Belle.
We're all here.
( sniffles )
It's getting darker.
I'm...
...sleepy.
It's all right.
Go to sleep.
We're all right here.
( sobs )