( instrument beeping )
( clicking chirps )
Is there a genetic match?
Yes. Let's gather the find
and bring it back to the ship.
Could this be it--
the proof?
If it is, we've just made
the most important discovery
in Voth history.
Opposable thumb.
Multiple articulations
in the digits--
as expected with
a technologically-advanced
species.
Hmm... his cranial capacity
is 22 percent smaller than ours,
and he appears to be
lacking a dilitus lobe.
He had no sense of smell?
If he did, it was rudimentary.
I doubt this fellow
would have enjoyed
the sulfur lagoons of Hokath.
His cartilaginous microstructure
is extremely porous.
Most likely warm-blooded.
I believe
this was a non-saurian.
"Non-saurian"?
Doesn't that weaken our case?
No. No, the genetic markers
we share with this being
are undeniable.
We are related,
however distantly.
The question we must answer is,
what was our endotherm doing
in this part of space?
Was he... on an expedition?
Did he have a ship?
Crewmates?
This material-- it's composed
of synthetic polymers,
and the molecular structure
suggests replication technology.
And consider
the garment itself--
is this marking
purely decorative,
or does it have
a symbolic function?
Could it indicate status?
Possibly a military uniform.
At the very least,
we can assume he was part of
a social infrastructure,
and that would imply a ship.
Did your eyes see the
planet of our origin?
The true home
of our race?
Was it... beautiful?
Was it covered
by oceans, by sand?
Were there nine moons
above your head?
Were there none?
( chuckles )
He appears to be
at a loss for words.
His ship and the people on it
hold the key
to where we came from.
We've got to find it.
I'll contact our supporters
at the Circle of Archeology.
They might be able
to spare a research vessel,
perhaps a few assistants.
This isn't a field trip, Veer.
We need to mount
a sector-wide expedition.
And that means a fleet of ships.
We have to go directly
to the Ministry of Elders.
Professor, don't you think
that's a little precipitous?
Bone decalcification indicates
he died more than a year ago.
His ship could be thousands
of light-years away by now.
Time is running out.
You must remember,
Veer, from the moment
you were initiated
into my circle,
you made a commitment
to the pursuit of
scientific truth.
Before this, all we
had was a theory.
Now we have proof.
We simply have to get them
to open their eyes
and see it.
We're going to set a
course for the city ship,
present our friend here
and let him
do the talking.
For millions of years,
our people have believed
that we were
the first intelligent beings
to evolve in this region
of space--
the first race.
This assumption underlies
everything that we hold dear.
But that belief has been
questioned in recent years
not only by the Circles
of Science and Philosophy
but by common people as well.
Lying before you is proof
of the Distant
Origin Theory.
These remains
demonstrate beyond doubt
that we arose elsewhere
in this galaxy,
that we evolved
on a faraway planet
and traveled to this space
millions of years ago,
our true history lost.
A pile of bones.
Impressive.
This "pile of bones"
belonged to a being
who died
approximately one year ago
from a species
found nowhere in known space.
And yet, we share 47 genetic
markers with this being.
We are undoubtedly
related to him.
And I intend to prove to you
that we evolved on
the very same planet he did.
And that planet is
the long-lost world
of the Distant
Origin Theory.
Yes. That's exactly right.
And to find that planet--
our planet--
we must find a living member
of his kind.
I've created
a computer extrapolation.
We're looking for a race
of bipedal endotherms--
spacefaring
but technologically limited.
Based on their cranial capacity,
I'd say they're no more advanced
than most endotherms we've--
MALE:
"Endotherms"?
You're proposing that we are
related to a mammalian species?
Yes.
Which is why
I ask your permission
to launch an expedition and...
Let's talk about
your discovery.
I enjoyed
the colorful tale
of how you found
these remains.
It says here that you
paid a substantial sum
for their location.
I was dealing with traders.
They knew the location
of the cave.
I had no choice.
Have you considered
you were
the victim of a hoax?
I have analyzed every
micron of this skeleton.
I assure you, it's authentic.
Professor Gegen,
have you considered
the wider implications
of your... theory?
What do you mean?
By challenging Doctrine
you're suggesting that
everything we believe
about ourselves,
our history,
our ancient and
rightful claim
over this region of space,
the authority of
this Ministry itself...
is a lie.
That's not what
I'm saying at all.
However, in the light
of my discovery,
some of our beliefs
may have to be... reevaluated.
"Reevaluated."
We will... consider your
request for an expedition.
( echoey gong sounds )
( door clangs open, closed )
Well done, Professor.
Hardly.
I failed to anticipate
the level of ignorance
I would be facing.
What do we do now?
I want you
to arrange a meeting
with the Circle
of Exobiology.
We have supporters there.
Father, I'm concerned.
Unnecessarily.
I don't think they
were very receptive.
They don't need to be.
The evidence
will speak for itself
and word of my discovery
is already traveling.
If enough people
confront the Ministry...
Mathematics was never
your strong point, Father.
You might be overestimating
your support.
You don't believe me,
either, do you?
I...
I want to.
Our ancestors came
from somewhere else.
We don't even belong here?
It all just seems
so... incredible.
I'm disappointed in you.
Father, please...
let this go.
You're chasing a fantasy...
and you're wasting
your genius.
I'm worried about what's
going to happen to you
if you don't stop.
And what's going to happen
to you if I do stop?
To your children,
to all of Voth?
You'll continue
to live in ignorance...
progress held back
by ancient myth.
The truth must be known.
( door opens )
We've got to leave...
now.
What's happened?
I met
with the Circle of Exobiology.
They're... concerned.
There have been rumors.
About what?
The Ministry
has seized your research
and they're planning
to detain you.
On what charge?
Heresy against Doctrine.
I'll fight it.
It's too late.
Your supporters are frightened.
No one will back you.
I'll have to do this
on my own, then.
Go back to your family.
As long as
you're with me,
you're at risk.
I'm not leaving you,
Professor.
I've run an analysis
on the uniform marking.
I found what appears
to be a microscopic
identification code.
The translation matrix indicates
it's most likely a proper name.
A name?
Yes. I believe it's the name
of the endotherm's vessel.
We're looking
for something called...
Voyager.
GEGEN:
Across the vastness of space
to find one ship
among a sea of stars
is no simple matter.
And for many weeks,
we found nothing.
And then, fortune glanced
in our direction.
A trader from a space station
bordering the Nekrit Expanse
informed us of a curious group
of explorers
claiming to be from
the other side of the galaxy.
The merchants there spoke
of a vessel called Voyager.
They were able to help
us clarify certain details.
With this new information,
we began to acquire
other items and new evidence.
Our most significant find:
A canister of warp plasma
from Voyager's engines.
So now we are scanning space
for a matching signature.
Little is known
about these explorers,
but they call
themselves "human"
and they claim to
be traveling home
to a distant planet.
My thoughts are
with you, Frola,
as are those of
my colleague, Veer.
Ah, I just sent a transmission
to my daughter.
Was that wise?
I encrypted
the carrier signal.
There's no way
to trace it.
I hope you gave her
my regards.
Of course I did.
I've seen the tint
on your scales
when she's around.
I've let you into
my academic circle,
but now you wish to enter
my family as well?
No, Professor,
I would never presume...
You should know your place.
Traditionally, my family mates
with the family of Towt.
But... traditions are
meant to be broken.
( chuckling )
( warbling beeps )
It's the plasma signature.
Scanners have found a match--
a ship, 90 light-years away.
There are 148
life-forms aboard,
traveling at warp 6.2.
I'm engaging
spatial displacement.
It's unlikely
their primitive sensors
will be able to detect us
once we're out of phase.
Take us out of transwarp.
We don't want to pass them.
Done.
I have an image.
What do we say to them?
Nothing.
Not at the moment.
We stand to learn more
by observing them.
Once we've collected
the information we need,
and if they appear nonviolent,
we'll make contact.
( beeping )
Entering portation range.
We'll be looking for
their data storage devices,
analyzing their behavior--
anything that can tell us
who and what these people are.
Eyes open, Veer.
Interphase is stable.
Curious.
I didn't expect the smell.
Well, they are
mammals, after all.
Ah, over here.
Ah, this appears to be
a computer access terminal.
Simple binary system.
I've downloaded
their database.
I'll bet you it's
an anodyne relay.
No way. Plasma conduit.
Relay. I'm telling you,
I checked the conduit network.
My point exactly.
You're not an engineer.
I'll bet you.
Name it.
A male and female
interacting.
Let's observe.
Well?
Well...
go ahead and gloat.
The anodyne relays--
who would've guessed?
Just a shot in the dark.
And it hit the bull's-eye.
Tonight, you pay up.
Holodeck 2, Klingon
martial arts program.
No getting out of it
this time.
Courting behavior?
Exactly.
Note how the female,
through her
feigned antagonism,
encourages the male
in his attempt to mate.
There's no sign of vasodilation
in their skin.
Obviously, they never
evolved that ability,
which would explain
their reliance
on crude verbal interplay.
PARIS:
I'll see you tonight.
B.Y.O.B.
What?
Bring your own Bat'leth.
Bat'leth.
Report.
CHAKOTAY:
We've completed
long-range scans.
If we maintain
our present course,
we'll enter a region
of heavy tetryon radiation
within two days.
What's the alternative?
A three-month detour.
Tuvok, enhance the shields.
Lieutenant, hold our course.
Harry, continue your scans.
Yes, ma'am.
JANEWAY:
Let's access everything
known about tetryon radiation.
I want to take
every precaution...
Well, Veer, what can you observe
about their social structure?
It's obviously hierarchical
with clear differences
in status and rank.
The males appear to be
subordinate to that female.
Perhaps a matriarchy.
My conclusion exactly.
( console beeps )
This is strange.
I'm picking up
spatial fluctuations.
They're coming from the Bridge.
Source?
I'm not sure, but they're highly
localized
with modulating
phase variants.
It looks like some kind
of cloaking technology.
All stop.
Intruder alert.
( alarm blares )
We've exceeded
our welcome.
Let's get back to the ship.
What's wrong?
Some sort of force field.
TUVOK:
I've erected
a level-10 containment field
around the Bridge, Captain.
Scanning on all
subspace frequencies.
I'm picking up
two life-forms.
Localize them.
Mission Ops 1.
Professor...
Their force field
is disrupting our interphase.
I'm compensating.
I can at least get us
off this deck.
Show yourselves.
Captain, the life-forms
left the Bridge.
They're now on Deck 2,
Section 13, Mess Hall.
Seal off the deck.
TUVOK:
Deck 2 sealed.
Security team to the Mess Hall.
Intruders?
I don't see any intruders.
It would appear we've
underestimated our endotherms.
Maybe we should
make contact--
explain ourselves.
It may come to that.
Captain, I've analyzed
those spatial phase variants.
Bridge to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
Adjust hand phasers
to a dispersion frequency
of 1.85 gigahertz.
That should disrupt
their cloaking technology.
Acknowledged.
I've matched the frequency
of their shields.
I think we can
get off this...
Spatial fluctuations...
there.
Neelix, get down!
( clicking chirps )
( gasps )
Minor phaser burns
to the upper thoracic region--
nothing serious--
but I want to check
for cellular damage.
I'll run
a microcellular scan.
Begin a DNA
analysis as well.
I'd like to know more about
his molecular physiology.
A belated welcome aboard.
I'm Captain Janeway.
Now, who are you
and what have you done
with my First Officer?
( clicking chirps )
You must have a ship.
Is it cloaked?
( chirping )
We're not going
to hurt you.
We just want
to know why you...
His heart rate and body
temperature have dropped.
His metabolism is almost
completely shut down.
Is he dying?
I don't think so.
His autonomic nervous system
is still fully functional.
He's gone into some sort
of protective hibernation.
Treat his injuries, then
see if you can revive him.
Examine his technology.
I want to know what
we're up against.
Don't be alarmed.
You're on my research vessel.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Your instinct is to flee,
but I must warn you
there's a confinement field
around the table.
Just stay calm
and you won't hurt yourself.
What do you want from me?
Why did you invade our ship?
It wasn't an invasion.
We were on a field expedition
to learn more
about your species.
We meant no harm.
I'm a molecular paleontologist.
Do you always harpoon
the local wildlife?
An unfortunate mistake.
Veer is inexperienced
and he panicked.
Your people were firing at us.
I couldn't get to him.
So you took me instead.
Yes. A living specimen
of human.
I've been studying
your computer database,
and I have many questions.
The planet of your origin,
correct?
That's right. Earth.
Are there any of my kind there?
Any of my species?
Who are you?
Please, answer the question.
Look, drop the force field
and tell me what's going on.
Then, maybe we can make first
contact in a civilized way.
For what it's worth,
I'm a scientist, too.
Maybe I can help you find
whatever it is you're looking
for.
I won't bite.
Thanks.
My name's Chakotay.
Gegen.
All right, Gegen,
let's talk about Earth.
Your call sounded urgent.
With good reason.
I've analyzed
the alien's DNA.
There are 47 genetic markers
identical to those
found in human DNA.
That's more
than coincidence.
I thought so, too.
I ran a search
for those markers
in Earth's
paleontological database.
Take a look at this.
JANEWAY:
Incredible.
That's one way
of putting it.
It says here that those markers
appeared in hundreds
of Earth species, dating back
tens of millions of...
Their species
evolved on Earth?
Apparently so.
And from the look of it,
you and he are distant cousins.
I wonder how distant.
Transfer yourself
to Holodeck 2.
I think it's time
we took a stroll
through primeval history.
I've entered the genetic markers
into the holo-database.
Let's see if we can find
our closet relative.
Computer, analyze
the genetic markers
and search Earth's
fossil record.
Identify any ancestors
common to both humans
and the alien in Sick Bay.
Life-form found.
Display.
Genus eryops.
Devonian Era.
Eryops...
this creature lived
over 400 million years ago.
And is thought to be
the last common ancestor
of cold-blooded and
warm-blooded organisms.
Yes, yes.
Let's take the next step
in our little stroll.
Computer, what's
the most highly evolved
cold-blooded organism
to develop from the eryops?
Genus hadrosaur.
Cretaceous Era.
Display the life-form.
As I recall,
the hadrosaur vanished
when a mass
extinction occurred
at the end of
the Cretaceous Period.
What if the hadrosaur
didn't die off?
What if some of them
survived that extinction
and continued to evolve?
I could well imagine
this creature
giving rise to a more
complex life-form.
Certainly the building blocks
are there--
bipedal, grasping hands...
Computer, run a genome
projection algorithm.
If the hadrosaur
had continued to evolve
over the last 65 million years,
extrapolate the most probable
appearance.
Extrapolation complete.
Display life-form.
That creature napping
in Sick Bay...
is a dinosaur.
The question is:
Why have we never seen him
in the natural history museums?
If a saurian species
had developed
a language and technology,
you'd think they would have
left something behind,
but what if it evolved
on an isolated continent?
A land mass
that was destroyed.
Earth has been devastated by
countless natural disasters
over the course
of its history--
asteroids, volcanoes,
earthquakes.
All evidence
of your race could be
at the bottom of the ocean
or under kilometers of rock.
Obviously not all of my people
became extinct.
Some of them must have developed
space-faring technology
and left the planet.
And ended up here in
the Delta Quadrant.
Our true origins on Earth
lost over the eons,
replaced by Doctrine...
the myth that we were
the first race.
Now you understand
why I had to find your ship.
Next time, you might try
a simple "hello" first.
"Eyes open."
I'm afraid I let my own
prejudice get in the way.
I was... wary of you.
We have very poor relations
with non-saurian races.
Mammals in particular
are considered to be a...
lower life-form,
but I must admit, I've never
gotten to know one before.
I hope I've made
a good impression.
In fact you have.
Well, I suggest
we get back to Voyager.
Your friend Veer
is probably sick of
the mammalian food by now.
I can't do that.
Why not?
I've already
made arrangements
to meet my supporters
on the fourth colony.
They're waiting for us.
Tell them we'll be late.
You don't understand
what I'm up against.
I'm being charged with
heresy against Doctrine.
You're my only evidence.
If enough people see
living proof of my theory,
even the Ministry will be forced
to acknowledge the truth.
I can't let you go now.
Not until it's over.
I'm sorry.
PARIS:
This should to the trick.
TUVOK:
An apple?
You said you wanted
an organic test subject.
I was referring
to a bio-cylinder,
but the fruit will suffice.
Let's give it a try.
Fascinating.
This alien device is apparently
pushing the apple
slightly out of phase
with our space-time continuum.
A personal cloaking device.
More advanced than
any cloak I've ever seen.
( deep rumbling )
Mr. Kim?
I'm reading a massive spatial
displacement dead ahead.
Red Alert.
( alarm blares )
We're being probed.
Shields at maximum.
Hail them.
No response.
They're locking onto the ship
with an energy beam.
It's cutting right
through our shields.
It's some sort of transporter.
Report.
We've been beamed
inside the alien vessel.
We're losing power.
Switch to auxiliary.
I'm locked out
of command control.
All systems are
shutting down.
Arm yourselves.
Tuvok to Bridge.
Captain Janeway, respond.
Turbolifts are off-line.
Let's get
to a Jefferies tube.
( clicking chirps )
Tuvok, I hope
that's your stomach.
( chirping )
My tricorder's not working.
There appears to be a dampening
fie...
Tuvok?
Go.
I'm not going to...
That's an order,
Lieutenant.
KIM:
I can't get a single relay back
on-line.
Somehow, they've locked us
out of all primary systems.
Let's get down to
Main Engineering.
We can access the manual
override from there...
( whooshing )
Your vessel
is under our control.
GEGEN:
It's an automated message
from the Ministry of Elders.
It says that they've
captured the Voyager,
that if I don't return
to the city ship
and face my accusers,
they'll destroy my evidence...
kill everyone on board.
What are you
going to do?
I won't be responsible
for those deaths,
but if I go back now
without my support,
they'll discredit my theory,
suppress the truth.
That might be difficult
with the evidence
standing right beside you.
They've taken my ship.
It sounds to me
like we're all on trial here.
I've just laid in a course
for the city ship.
We're looking
for two of our own kind.
One was found
in your medical bay.
Where is the other?
I don't know.
He took my First Officer
and disappeared.
Our scans indicate
that your ship is alone.
Where do you come from?
If you want my cooperation,
I suggest you release
my vessel.
You are non-indigenous beings.
You have no rights
under Doctrine.
Where do you come from?
Apparently... we're from
the same place you are--
Earth.
I see that Gegen
has begun spreading his lies.
( equipment powering up )
( beeping )
Paris to Janeway.
Captain, if you can hear me,
I've got weapons control
and I've armed
a full spread of torpedoes.
Who's that?
My helmsman.
Sounds like he's
about to blast a hole
in the side of your ship.
Lieutenant Paris, fire.
You might want
to hold on to something.
COMPUTER:
Launch protocols
have been disrupted.
Switch to auxiliary protocols.
Unable to comply.
Weapon systems are off-line.
How?
Method unknown.
Paris to Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, someone
on the alien vessel
detected my launch sequence.
I don't know how they did it,
but I'm completely locked out.
Nice try, Tom.
Haluk to Command.
The Voyager's Captain
is proving uncooperative.
I request an interrogation
surgeon to assist with the...
MALE:
That won't be necessary.
Gegen is in custody.
Remain on the Voyager
and wait
for further instructions.
Professor Forra Gegen,
you are accused
of heresy against Doctrine.
Do you wish to
retract your claims
regarding
the Distant Origin Theory?
I do not.
Then we will proceed.
FEMALE:
Three months ago,
you circulated a study
criticizing what you called
"resistance to truth"--
once again,
disputing Doctrine.
I apologize if I wrote anything
that offended the Elders,
but I never even mentioned
the word "doctrine."
You didn't have to.
Your meaning was clear.
For nearly a decade,
you've used
the Distant Origin Theory
to attack and undermine
the guiding principles
of our society.
Not so! I've been pursuing
a scientific investigation.
I'm not concerned
at all with Doctrine!
My point exactly.
Your disregard for the effects
of your casual theorizing
is why you stand accused.
You are reckless and
irresponsible, and you are
a destructive influence
to our society.
But it is not too late
for you to redress
the damage you have done.
Disavow your claims.
Acknowledge your mistakes
and this Ministry
will show you leniency.
I'm sorry.
I can't deny the evidence.
The proof is standing
right beside me.
Proof? Really?
Our scientists have
analyzed your data.
Their conclusion:
"These creatures are
not related to us at all.
"The genetic similarities
are a result of random
convergence, nothing more."
If I may speak?
Voyager's database contains
a complete fossil record
of my planet.
Your genetic markers appear
not only in humans
but in hundreds of species
throughout our history.
That's a lot
of "random convergence."
If you'd take a look
at the data...
We have.
The data isn't in question.
Your interpretation is.
Professor Gegen,
I don't want to be here
any more than you do,
and frankly, I would prefer
not to be responsible
for disgracing one of
our most venerable scientists.
All I ask is that
you admit the possibility
that your interpretation
is wrong.
Will you at least do that?
I will admit that there
are still questions.
The picture is incomplete.
But I am certain of this:
We are from the planet
these humans call Earth.
There are those who disagree.
Tova Veer, you are
an accomplished young scientist.
You were initiated
into the Circle of Archaeology
with the highest of honors.
Yes, Minister.
And you have been
Professor Gegen's assistant
for six years.
I've had that privilege.
You are familiar--
intimately involved with
all of your mentor's research
regarding the so-called
Distant Origin Theory?
That is correct.
In your expert evaluation,
what is the validity
of the Professor's analysis?
It is flawed, Minister.
Veer!
You're saying you and Gegen
were mistaken?
Yes.
I've reviewed
all of his research,
including data
from the Voyager's computer.
I've checked and rechecked
the procedures.
I now believe
that we were... overzealous.
We saw an evolutionary
connection
when, in fact, there was none.
Enthusiasm and passion
are never wrong, Veer.
Your only mistake was allowing
them to distort your judgment.
You may go.
Professor Gegen,
I will ask you again:
Could you be mistaken?
What did you say to him?
That you'd take away his honors
if he didn't cooperate?
That you'd send him
to a detention colony?
Could you be mistaken?
Did you threaten his family?!
Respond to the question!
No! Why should I?
You've already made up
your mind.
This inquiry isn't
about evidence and proof.
It's about keeping you
in that chair!
Gegen!
It's about
maintaining a myth
that keeps the Ministry
in power.
You'd do anything
to silence me.
Well, it won't work.
I'll never
retract my claims.
I'd rather go to prison
than help you
perpetuate ignorance!
Your true scales
are finally showing.
You're right, Minister.
I was mistaken.
I thought you might actually
care about the truth,
even if it
called into question
some of our
deepest beliefs, and...
We are not immigrants!
I will not deny 20 million years
of history and Doctrine
just because one insignificant
saurian has a theory.
One last time:
Could you be mistaken?
It's you who are
mistaken, Minister.
What?
You accuse Gegen of having
his objectivity clouded
by... wishful thinking,
but aren't you guilty
of the same charge?
I am not on trial here.
I understand,
but, in a way, your beliefs are.
How you think about yourselves,
your place in the universe--
that is on trial
and this isn't the first time.
What do you mean?
I've had the opportunity
over the last few days
to learn something
about your culture--
your great accomplishments.
Consider the breakthrough
into transwarp.
An incredible achievement,
and yet,
your ancient Doctrine predicted
terrible disasters
if it were even attempted.
That held your race back
for millennia
until someone took a chance
and challenged
that prediction.
They succeeded,
and your society
entered a new chapter
of exploration
and your Doctrine
was changed accordingly.
I know from the history
of my own planet
that change is difficult.
New ideas are often greeted
with skepticism-- even fear.
But sometimes
those ideas are accepted
and when they are...
progress is made.
Eyes are opened.
When I open my eyes
to this theory,
what I see appalls me.
I see my race fleeing
your wretched planet--
a group of pathetic refugees
crawling and scratching
their way across the galaxy,
stumbling into this domain.
I see a race with no birthright,
no legacy.
That is unacceptable.
I see something very
different, Minister--
an ancient race
of saurians,
probably the first
intelligent life on Earth--
surrounded
by some of the most
terrifying creatures
that ever lived.
And yet they thrived,
developed language
and culture and technology.
And when the planet
was threatened with disaster,
they boldly launched themselves
into space,
crossed what must have seemed
like unimaginable distances,
facing the unknown every day,
but somehow,
they stayed together,
kept going with the same courage
that had served them before
until they reached
this Quadrant,
where they laid the foundation
of what was to become
the great Voth culture.
Deny that past...
and you deny the struggle and
achievements of your ancestors.
Deny your origins on Earth...
and you deny your true heritage.
Do you retract
your claims?
No.
I stand by them.
Very well.
It is my judgment
you will suffer
the consequences
of your obstinacy.
Gegen, you are guilty
of heresy against Doctrine
and will be placed
on a detention colony.
For as long as you breathe,
you will neither teach
nor engage in research.
Your life
as a scientist has ended.
As you wish.
Chakotay
of the Voyager starship,
you, your Captain and her crew
will join Professor Gegen.
Why? You have nothing to gain
by imprisoning them.
Let them go.
You will spend
the remainder of your lives
on a detention colony.
Your ship will be destroyed.
Minister...
You will surrender
your vessel immediately,
and inform your crew
that this judgment...
Stop this, please!
Are you offering me
an alternative?
I have...
reconsidered
and I retract
my claims
regarding
the Distant Origin Theory.
My analysis of the data
was obviously flawed.
I was...
mistaken.
You are prepared to refute
your work publicly
before the Circles of Science?
Yes.
You will then be assigned
to another area of research.
Surely paleontology
has become tiresome to you
after so many years.
Perhaps metallurgical analysis
would be a more rewarding
vocation for you.
Perhaps.
I am not unreasonable.
You were drawn into this...
situation
through no fault
of your own.
You are to be returned
to your ship
where you will set course
away from our territory.
It would be
in your best interest
if I never saw you again.
( gong sounds )
I'm not so good
at chemistry.
My career
as a metallurgical scientist
is likely to be...
undistinguished.
I'm sorry.
I was foolish.
Arrogant...
and I lost everything.
You were courageous,
as the Voth have always been
from the first time
they left Earth.
And you, Chakotay,
have been a colleague...
a friend.
I will not forget you.
There's something else
I hope you never forget.
Someday, every Voth
will see this as home.
Someday.
Eyes open.
Chakotay to Voyager--
energize.