Where are you going?
You were doing great.
You were in perfect position
to deliver the death blow.
All you had to do
was follow through.
Come on.
Let's try it again.
Don't push me, Tom.
Huh! I am not pushing you.
I'm encouraging you.
To do what?
Try something new.
This martial-arts program
is the best workout
I've ever had.
No, it's more than that.
Working with
a bat'leth is an art.
You have to use your mind
and body, your movements--
Look, you may find
all of this Klingon stuff
really fascinating,
but I don't.
I'm not going
to waste my time
trying to disembowel a bunch
of holographic monsters.
I only came down here
because you tricked me
into that stupid bet.
Would you watch it.
You could take somebody's
head off with that thing.
( panting )
I have tried this,
and now I am finished.
Got it?
Look, if you don't like
the program, that's fine,
but why do you always
have to get so hostile?
I am not hostile!
Where am I?
Paris to Bridge. We have
an alien visitor on Deck 6.
What do you want with me?
Why have I been abducted?
We didn't abduct you.
You just appeared here.
We had nothing to do with it.
What is this place?
You're on a starship
called Voyager.
Where were you before?
My colony on Nyria III.
I was walking home
and... then I was here.
What's wrong?
It's cold here...
and too bright.
Let us take you
to Sick Bay.
Our Doctor can run some scans.
Maybe we can get some answers.
I've increased the temperature
to 45 degrees Celsius.
And the light
level should be
more comfortable
for you now.
Yes, thank you.
You're very considerate.
I hope you'll excuse
my initial suspicion.
This experience
has been very unnerving.
I'd feel the same way
in your place.
Do your people
possess technology
which could have
transported you here?
Not that I know of.
I've heard of other races
that have it.
Maybe one of them
brought me here,
but I can't imagine why.
Please describe the
physical sensation
of your experience.
First, I felt lightheaded
and then everything
around me
seemed to bend or ripple.
There-- There was
a moment of blackness
and I felt
a curious sensation
of insects crawling
on my skin
and then I found myself
on your ship.
Interesting.
I'll run a microcellular
scan for residual energy traces.
Can you tell us
where your colony is located?
We're on the third planet
of the Nyrian system.
A red giant star
with a large cloud
of interstellar dust
just beyond the fifth planet.
Doesn't sound like any
system we've encountered.
Unfortunately,
our knowledge
of this area of
space is limited.
I'd like you to look
at a star chart
to see if you recognize
any astronomical markers.
Of course.
In the meantime, my crew
has begun scanning the area
for any clues about
what happened to you.
DOCTOR:
Lieutenant,
if you don't mind.
Where is Kes today?
I don't know.
She's late for
her duty shift.
Computer, locate Kes.
COMPUTER:
Kes is not on board Voyager.
When did she leave?
1132 hours.
What time did our alien
visitor come on board?
1132 hours.
There's nothing to indicate
that any other ships
have been in this area for weeks
and the nearest
inhabited world
is over ten
light-years away.
Whoever or whatever did this
had to leave
some kind of energy trace.
Internal sensors aren't
showing anything unusual
in the corridor
where the Nyrian appeared
or at Kes's
last known location.
Then let's concentrate
on the time.
Run a level-1 analysis
on all sensor readings,
internal and external, taken at
the exact moment it happened.
I'll get it started,
but it may take a while.
You don't think
I'm hostile, do you?
I, uh... wouldn't describe you
that way, no.
I know that I have a temper,
but that doesn't mean
that I'm always hostile,
does it?
No, of course not.
I am forthright.
I speak my mind.
That is very different
from being hostile.
Very different.
And if someone
described me that way,
they'd be way off
the mark, wouldn't they?
Way off.
Then why do you look like
you're afraid for your life?
( console beeping )
What is this?
Looks like a surge
of polaron particles.
Localize the source.
I'll try to increase
the sensor resolution.
You have anything yet?
Harry?
Torres to Bridge.
Ensign Kim just disappeared.
And we just got
another visitor.
Mr. Tuvok, have you
made any progress?
Increasing the shield strength
has had no apparent effect.
However, if--
Oh...
Welcome to Sick Bay.
Take a number.
In the last three hours,
we've lost 22 of our people.
According to the Nyrians,
they've all shown up
on their colony
as though
we're switching places.
I went over our navigational
charts with Dammar,
but he's completely unfamiliar
with this part of space.
For all we know,
that colony could be
thousands
of light-years away.
Any idea what might be
causing these transfers?
I'm not sure.
Harry and I detected
a surge of polaron particles
right before he disappeared.
They created a spatial
distortion field around him,
but it collapsed
as soon as he vanished.
Could it have been some
kind of spatial anomaly?
It could
have been anything.
A naturally occurring
phenomenon like a wormhole,
or a subspace
flow field or a kind
of technology
like our transporters.
JANEWAY:
All right.
Get back to your stations
and keep looking.
Confine the Nyrians
to the cargo bays
and post security details
at every access point.
CHAKOTAY:
In all fairness,
Captain, they haven't been
threatening in any way.
They seem as puzzled
by all this as we are.
Chakotay, I don't care
how they seem.
All I care about is that I've
had a knot in my stomach
since the first Nyrian arrived.
Something about this is wrong;
I can smell it.
Look at us,
running around the ship
checking sensors
and spinning theories
while the Nyrians slowly replace
our crew.
Consider this:
There has been
a consistent interval
of nine minutes and 20 seconds
between these exchanges.
At that rate, our entire crew
will be gone in 18 hours.
Tell me that doesn't put
a knot in your stomach.
You have your orders.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50912.4.
It's been 12 hours
since these
mysterious exchanges began
and we still haven't discovered
their cause.
I've already lost
over half my crew.
Cargo Bay 2 is almost full.
We'll have to start
converting the shuttle bays.
Then do it. I want them where
we can keep an eye on them.
I'll have to reassign
more crew members to security.
Our ranks are getting
a little thin.
Shut down everything but the
ship's essential functions.
We'll be operating on a
skeleton crew before long.
B'Elanna,
you've developed a theory
about what's happening.
A Nyrian astrophysicist who
arrived about an hour ago
told me about some strange
graviton fluctuations
they detected
at their colony.
I ran some scans on this end
and found the same thing.
JANEWAY:
A wormhole?
Possibly a baby one.
And if I'm right,
one end is opening
intermittently inside Voyager.
We could have passed through it
while it was forming
and snagged on it somehow.
Then how do we
get it unsnagged?
Well, now that I have
this new information I'd like
to have another talk with
Rislan, the Nyrian scientist.
Is Neelix still helping out
with the new arrivals?
I think he's
in Cargo Bay 2 now.
Janeway to Neelix.
Neelix here, Captain.
I'd like you to find
one of the Nyrians who--
Neelix to Captain Janeway.
I lost contact.
What did you say?
Chakotay to Neelix.
The Captain's gone.
We need you to find
a Nyrian scientist called Rislan
and get him to Engineering
as soon as you can.
Right away, Commander.
Do what you have to do
to get some answers, B'Elanna.
Excuse me.
Aren't you Dr. Rislan?
It's still
too cold in here.
I'll adjust the environmental
controls... again.
But I must ask you...
And the air is too humid.
I'll take care of it
right away.
But I must ask you to go
to our Engineering room.
I believe you're
urgently needed.
I trust it will be suitably
warm and dark there?
We'll make sure
you're comfortable.
A security guard
will escort you.
GUARD:
Right away, sir.
Commander, there's a problem
with the internal sensors
on Deck 4.
It looks like a circuit relay
malfunction.
I can't spare anyone
for repairs.
You'll have to make do.
How do you like your first day
as Chief of Security, Ensign?
It's everything
I dreamed of, sir.
Who says there's no room for
advancement on this ship?
( beeping )
Another disappearance.
It's Neelix.
How many people
does that leave us?
Forty.
And more than
a hundred Nyrians.
I want access to all systems
restricted to authorized
voiceprints only.
Seal off any part of the ship
that we're not using
and place security force fields
around sensitive areas.
Warp core, armory,
torpedo bays.
And let's hope
I'm just being paranoid.
RISLAN:
If you ask me, a tetryon scan
is a waste of time.
A multispectral sweep
would be much more useful.
TORRES:
Actually, I didn't ask
and I've already initiated
the tetryon scan.
You're the expert.
Neutrinos, ionized hydrogen,
theta-band radiation...
Just what you'd expect
to find in a wormhole.
But it's what we're not finding
that I'm interested in.
The scan shows no quantum level
fluctuations whatsoever.
That's not so unusual.
It's more than unusual;
it's impossible.
I don't think this is
a wormhole at all.
Perhaps it's a subspace
flow field then.
I'm going to run
a pattern analysis
from the original data.
( beeping )
Nope, definitely not
a flow field.
The spatial harmonics
are incompatible.
I don't think this is
a natural phenomenon.
( grunts )
Don't move.
I won't hurt you
unless you force me to.
Your people have been
behind this all along.
What are you doing?
Moving you
to the head of the line.
B'Elanna, are
you all right?
Captain, the Nyrians
are responsible
for the exchanges.
I think they have
some kind of technology...
What do they want with us?
I don't know.
They refuse to answer
any questions.
They've given us food,
water and medical supplies,
everything but information.
Where's the rest of the crew?
In other compounds
just like this one
scattered
throughout the woods.
This doesn't seem
like a Nyrian colony.
It's not warm enough
or dark enough for them.
Exactly. It's more like
an idyllic version of Earth,
as though it were created
specifically for us.
Do we have any idea
what planet we're on?
Not yet. I sent Tuvok to
investigate the other compounds
and see what he can find out.
Until he gets back,
all we have are
unanswered questions.
Decks 11 through 15
are completely shut down.
Most of the remaining crew
are on security detail
near the cargo
and shuttle bays.
What, all 13 of them?
Twelve, sir.
( beeping )
Crewman Gennaro to Bridge.
I'm in Engineering,
and I just found Ensign Molina.
He's unconscious but okay.
What about the Nyrian
scientist he was watching?
There's no sign of him, sir.
Find him.
That's a priority.
Where are you going?
To have a talk
with the Nyrians.
Chakotay to all hands.
Security alert.
The Nyrians may be trying
to take control of the ship.
Everyone get to the Bridge
or Main Engineering
and secure them
against possible intruders.
Second team,
take control of weapons.
( door opens )
Start by reinforcing
the containment fields.
( thumping )
Reroute emergency power.
We've got to seal those doors.
( grunts )
( groans )
( indistinct commands )
They're everywhere.
They're even decrypting
our access codes.
The Nyrians obviously
prepared for this
before they got here.
They must have tapped into
our computer somehow
and gotten enough information
to plan this mission
down to the letter.
Larson?
Chakotay to anybody who's left.
Please respond.
Gennaro here, sir.
Anybody else?
The two of us
aren't going to win this.
So we might as well make life
as difficult for the Nyrians
as we can.
Sabotage everything
you can get your hands on.
Understood.
Good luck.
What's our status?
We have shut off their security
measures on all decks.
We should have full
computer access soon.
But their navigational
controls are not working.
Not working?
There are two humans still
moving through the ship.
They seem intent
on causing damage.
Find them.
( engine powering down )
They're sabotaging
the power systems.
The antimatter reactor's
shutting down.
FEMALE: I can't see.
MALE: What happened?
This way.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Disabling
lateral EPS relays
may disrupt computer functions
throughout the ship.
Let's hope so.
Chakotay to Gennaro.
They're trying to delete
the Doctor's program.
Are you anywhere near Sick Bay?
Gennaro?
Computer...
how long ago did Crewman Gennaro
leave the ship?
COMPUTER:
Seven minutes and 20 seconds.
I've located
the last human.
He's on the fifth deck.
Send a patrol
to stop him.
I already have.
Activate emergency
medical holographic program.
DOCTOR:
Please state the nature...
Hello?
Doctor, over here.
Commander, what's happening?
Your program's
going to be deleted
unless I can download you
into the mobile emitter
before I disappear,
which should be any second now.
( thudding )
Got it.
All right.
I know when to quit.
I've never been completely
cut off from the ship before.
What if the emitter's
power supply runs out?
Let's hope we're not stuck here
long enough to find out.
Tuvok, what did you learn?
There are ten compounds
like this one
spread over approximately
four square kilometers.
They are surrounded
on all sides by wilderness.
FEMALE:
Could I have your attention?
Now that you've
all arrived here safely,
I'd like to welcome you
to your new home.
I'm not particularly
interested in being welcomed.
Why have you brought us here?
Your vessel will
be used to defend
Nyrian acquisitions.
Is this the way
you operate?
Gradually changing places
with the crew of a ship?
Ships, colonies,
space stations.
We've found it's far more
effective than warfare.
We aren't
a cruel people.
We've tried to make
this experience
as painless as possible,
and as you can see,
we've gone to great lengths
to create an environment
in which you
will be comfortable.
Nonetheless,
we are being held here
against our will.
Well, I'm afraid
that's unavoidable.
But I think
you'll be happy here.
The food dispensers
have been programmed
with selections
from your own computer files.
We have even downloaded
literature and entertainment
from your cultural database.
What happens if we try to leave
this little paradise?
I think you'll find
there's nowhere to go.
We don't accept that.
We will find a way
out of here.
Captain...
your lack of gratitude
is unbecoming.
You and your crew
could have found yourselves
somewhere far less hospitable.
It's still
a prison.
If you want to be miserable
here, that is your choice.
But since there's nothing
you can do about your situation,
I suggest you accept it...
gracefully.
We're ready now.
Tuvok... tell me about
this wilderness you found.
How rugged is it?
Can we walk out?
I don't believe so.
In every direction I went,
I encountered
a natural barrier.
A sheer cliff,
an impassable river.
These obstacles completely
surround the colony.
A perfectly isolated area.
Doesn't that seem
a bit convenient?
This place does have
an artificial quality.
I wouldn't be surprised if
the whole thing is holographic
and the wilderness
was created
to keep us
from exploring too far.
Captain.
Uh...
sorry for the intrusion,
but I-I wanted to welcome you.
I'm, uh... Jarleth...
your neighbor.
Where did you come from?
My people live in
the other environment,
uh, through that portal.
It's, uh, quite different.
More, uh... desert-like.
This place, it's
so, uh... green.
But I'm sure
it's suitable for you.
The Nyrians undoubtedly
had a good look
through your data banks.
Were your people brought
here by the Nyrians?
They took us one by one.
Oh, is this what you eat?
JANEWAY:
They took you from your colony.
They claimed not to know
what was happening.
By the time we
got suspicious,
there were
too many of them.
We've been here
ever since.
Do you have any idea
where "here" is?
No. Uh-uh.
Mmm.
Not bad.
Um, would you
be interested
in trading for
some of these?
The last inhabitants of this
environment
had no concept
of a barter system,
but you strike me
as a much more, uh...
sophisticated group.
If there were people here before
us,
maybe we could
get out the same way.
Oh, I... I don't think
you'd like their method
of escape.
Uh... they all died
from a plague.
Captain,
there must be some kind of
force field here,
but I can't find it.
Pretty well-camouflaged,
isn't it?
It took me almost nine years to
find the portal.
How did you get it open?
Well, I...
I have my ways.
I'd consider that
information
a valuable commodity.
Well, I'd be happy
to make a trade,
but the portal only leads
into our environment.
You're welcome
to, uh, visit, of course.
There may be
other portals...
if you can show us
how to find them.
I look forward
to our collaboration.
What do you see now?
Fascinating.
Everything is glowing with its
own energy.
Even the plants are emitting
a faint thermal signature.
It's really
quite lovely.
Aside from
the aesthetic consideration,
how's your optical resolution?
The Captain sent me down
to get an update.
Well, we're
just about ready.
I've reconfigured
the Doctor's optical sensors.
And, as soon as they're aligned,
he should be able to detect
the microwave signature
of the portals.
Then I can begin my new career
as a tricorder.
About the other day...
I might have been a bit...
oversensitive, uh,
about the Klingon program.
Don't worry about it.
That should
just about do it.
I think we can
start scanning now.
Good. I'll tell
the Captain.
Um...
about the program...
I-I didn't mean to push you.
I know. You didn't.
And I didn't mean to, um,
lash out at you like that.
A typical defensive reaction,
using an aggressive outburst
as a shield
against a perceived
emotional threat.
That says it, all right.
Oh, that's very funny
coming from you.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Well, you're hardly one
to talk about being defensive.
And why is that exactly?
Well, you just pretend
that nothing bothers you,
and then you turn everything
into a joke.
DOCTOR:
That's a valid observation.
Defense mechanisms
come in many forms.
That's ridiculous.
I am an easygoing person...
( chuckles )
who is just trying to be
friendly to someone
who is obviously terrified
of having a friend.
Fear of intimacy is a common
indication of low self-esteem.
Perhaps if you stopped
to analyze the root cause,
you might--
If you find it so difficult
to be my friend,
then why keep trying?
That's a good question.
I think I'll stop
wasting my time.
( sighs )
I pulled a power cell
and some relay circuits
out of a food dispenser.
And this little thing looks
like some sort of capacitor.
It should do.
If you can find
another like this one,
we'll be able to construct
a second weapon.
You're assuming
the first one will work.
Yes.
I'll get on it right away.
Maybe if I take apart
the sonic shower assembly.
I've got to give
you credit, Tuvok.
Working on the fly
with nothing but random parts
with no guide
to follow...
I never thought Vulcans
had much of a knack
for improvising.
Our circumstances seem to
require a certain flexibility.
You could say that.
This reminds me
of those survival classes
they put us through
at the Academy.
Surprise tactical simulations.
Getting dropped off
in the woods
with no chance to prepare.
They certainly taught you
to live by your wits.
That was a lesson
I had already learned.
During the Rite of tal'oth,
I survived in the Vulcan
desert for four months
with a ritual blade
as my only possession.
After that, Starfleet
training exercises
seemed less
of a challenge.
I guess so.
( beeping softly )
This weapon is complete.
When Mr. Neelix returns
with a second capacitor, I'll...
improvise another.
Lieutenant, I haven't seen
any sign of a portal.
Frankly, I'm getting
tired of this.
Holograms don't get tired.
Keep looking.
We've tried to get
out of here for years.
The closest I ever came
was finding the portal
between our two
environments.
I-I don't mean
to be pessimistic,
but I don't think
there is a way out.
There must be-- we just
have to keep looking.
Well, I know it's too early
for you to accept this,
but life here isn't so bad.
Once we stopped
trying to escape,
we actually began
enjoying ourselves.
TORRES:
Captain, we found something.
It's directly in front of me.
Here?
Yes, right there.
Well, if my scanning services
are no longer required,
I'll return
to my medical duties.
We can cover more ground
if we split up.
Tuvok and I will take
this direction.
You three go that way.
We'll meet back here
in 20 minutes.
I don't think we're
supposed to be in here.
B'Elanna, over here.
There's another one.
Self-contained biospheres.
Every one of them different.
It's definitely some kind
of control station.
I can bring up information,
but I can't understand
what it says.
If the Nyrians downloaded
Voyager's cultural database,
you may be able to tap into
the translation algorithm.
Oh, much better.
"The Federation habitat.
Population: 148."
At least they haven't detected
that anyone's missing.
Here's another environment.
And another.
How many are there?
Captain, there's data here
for 94 different environments.
They're holding
thousands of prisoners.
There's got to be something
that'll tell us about
the layout of this place.
( buzzing )
Authorized access only.
I'll try to bypass
their security codes.
Good.
I'm getting something.
Incredible, Tuvok.
We're on a ship.
We should attempt
to locate the Bridge.
If there is one,
I can't find it, but...
( door opening )
There seems to be a more
extensive command center
four decks above us.
Maybe I can access it from here.
( beeping )
More security lockouts.
We may need to disable
the entire security subroutine.
( alarm blaring )
There's been an unauthorized
access at one of the terminals.
Some of the life-forms
have escaped their habitat.
Find them
and put them back.
We are attempting
to do that now.
However, if they resist,
stronger measures
may become necessary.
If they leave you
no other alternative...
you have the authorization
to use force.
How soon can we go to warp?
I want to get back there.
Just a few minutes.
Let's go back.
No. We've got to find
the Captain and Tuvok.
They might need our help.
We have to help ourselves.
This is our chance to get back
into our own environments.
If you want to go, then go.
We're not leaving them behind.
MALE:
Don't move.
I surrender.
I'm sorry. It wasn't my idea.
They made me come along.
They, uh...
went around that corner.
Follow them.
He just activated
a translocator control.
One life-form was sent
from an access tunnel
to the biosphere
adjacent to ours.
That must have been Jarleth.
This translocator is
what the Nyrians used
to get on our ship.
Then we should be able
to use the same method
to return to Voyager.
Assuming we can figure
out how to use it.
( console beeping )
We're getting
an incoming transmission
from the biosphere vessel.
Audio only.
Taleen to Dammar.
Some of the life-forms have
accessed the control systems.
They have weapons.
We need reinforcements.
We're on our way to you now.
Increase speed
to maximum velocity
and take us close enough
to translocate
my entire security force
at once!
Yes, sir.
Something's wrong
with the phaser.
The power cell's
probably running out.
These aren't exactly
Starfleet issue.
We've got to get out
of these tunnels.
There must be
somewhere to hide
in one of
these habitats.
Tom, I think I found one.
Here it is.
Remember how we had
to warm up the ship
for the Nyrians?
This is the last place
they'd want to follow us.
Stop!
Follow them.
That's an order.
This translocator has
an extremely long range,
over ten light-years.
Great distances must
limit its capacity.
That's why the Nyrians could
only send
one person to Voyager at a time
and bring one of us here.
Their method has
the added advantage
of appearing innocent,
at least in the beginning.
I can't find
the command pathways
to get the system operative
and I don't imagine
we have much longer
before they find us.
Maybe coming in here
wasn't such a good idea.
Let's hope it's worse
for them than it is for us.
Careful.
That phaser's just about dead.
They can't last much longer.
We've just got to stay
one step ahead of them.
We don't want to get too
far away from the portal.
Maybe we should find
a place to hide.
( panting )
Let me see the phaser.
My hands are completely numb.
Here.
I would have thought all
that hot Klingon blood
would have kept you warm.
Shows how much you know
about Klingons.
They have much less tolerance
for the cold than humans do.
Really? I thought
that was Cardassians.
No, they just complain
about it more.
Better?
I think that'll amplify
the power cell...
enough for one more shot.
( footsteps approach )
( groaning )
B'Elanna.
Nice shot.
Now, let's get out of here
before we freeze to death.
JANEWAY:
I've got the basic
operation down,
but I can't quite figure out
how to lock on to a target.
Can you access anything
that might function
like our targeting scanners?
There are bio-sensors
contained within
the monitoring programs
of each habitat.
Perhaps...
What is it?
I'm detecting human life-forms
in one of the environments.
The Argala habitat.
Tom and B'Elanna.
Possibly.
They may have taken refuge there
to hide from the Nyrians.
Doesn't look very inviting,
does it?
The temperature
is minus 20 degrees Celsius.
They can't last long in that.
We've got to get them out.
( beeping )
Captain, there's a ship
approaching at high warp.
It's Voyager.
If the Nyrians are
bringing in reinforcements,
we're in trouble. Keep
working on those bio-scanners.
I didn't think we were this far
from the portal.
( cries out )
I don't think
I can go on any farther.
You have to
keep moving.
Oh, I'm so sleepy.
No, B'Elanna, get up.
No, you go on.
I'm just going to rest here.
If you do that, you'll die.
No, I'll be fine.
I just have to close my eyes
for a minute.
Oh, no, I am not going
to let you do this.
On your feet now, Torres.
That's an order!
You can't give me orders.
We're the same rank.
I am a Bridge officer,
and I have seniority.
Oh, yeah,
by about two days.
On your feet, now! Come on.
You been wanting to take
a swing at me for days.
Now's your chance.
You're just trying
to get me moving.
You will keep moving.
Or do I have to throw you
over my shoulder
and carry you out?
Don't even try it.
Where are we?
The... Argala habitat, sir.
Get us out of here.
Where's the portal?
You did this.
I've taken control
of your translocation system.
My Tactical Officer
is standing by
waiting for my next order.
And-And what
would that be?
That depends on you.
Surrender my ship...
and release
all the prisoners here.
Unacceptable.
All right.
You can stay where you are,
and greet
your fellow crew members
as we translocate them here
to join you.
And if we do surrender?
We'll find you
a nice, warm habitat
where you'll be comfortable
while we contact the native
worlds of your prisoners
and arrange for their return.
And once we've disabled
your translocator...
you'll be free to go.
I'm sorry you don't wish
to be reasonable.
Mr. Tuvok, get me out of here
and prepare to--
No! Wait!
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50929.6.
The Nyrians
have surrendered Voyager,
and my crew
is safely back onboard.
The former prisoners
on the habitat vessel
have contacted
their native worlds
and are waiting
to be taken home.
Nice day.
Beautiful.
( sighs )
Things were pretty chilly
there for a while.
I guess they were.
Feels good to be warm again.
Yeah.
Sure does.
( sighs )