Where you headed?
The Bridge.
Mind if I walk with you?
Not at all.
So, how's it going?
Not bad, I guess.
Tuvok still giving you
a hard time?
No more than usual.
I don't know about you,
but when I think about
spending 70 years
on the same ship with that guy,
it gives me a headache.
I get the impression a lot
of the crew agrees with me--
Maquis and Starfleet.
Bridge.
So what do you think?
About what?
About what
I've been saying,
that a lot of the crew
aren't too happy
with our Chief of Security,
and for that matter,
I don't think Captain Janeway
is winning any
popularity contests, either.
Don't you agree?
Why do I get the feeling
that you're testing me?
Let's just say I'm interested
in your opinion.
Why?
You're a good officer.
I like you,
and I wouldn't want
to see you get hurt.
Computer,
halt turbolift.
Look, what's this all about?
There are going to be
some changes around here.
All of the Maquis are
in line, and about 25
of the Starfleet crew
are with us.
Are you saying there's
going to be a mutiny?
And when the
shooting starts...
I'm going to need to know
which side you're on.
( door opens )
Well, Commander...
Voyager's all yours.
There's a first time
for everything, I guess.
Don't worry, Captain, I'll keep
your ship safe and sound.
I'm sure you will.
PARIS:
Shuttle Bay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Mr. Paris.
The shuttle's ready to go,
whenever you are.
On my way.
Captain,
I've been thinking.
Are you sure
you don't want to take
Lieutenant Tuvok with you,
just in case the Rukani
turn out to be less friendly
than they seem?
I assure you, Commander, I have
made thorough preparations
for the Captain's safety
during her away mission.
You, on the other hand,
are still adapting to
your duties as First Officer.
Under the circumstances,
I believe my time
will be better spent
assisting you in your effort
to justify the trust the Captain
has placed in you.
I appreciate your concern
for my safety,
Mr. Chakotay,
but Tuvok's right.
Lieutenant Paris and I
will be just fine.
I'll see you in 24 hours.
Lieutenant...
I want you to keep close tabs
on the Captain's shuttle.
Let's make sure she doesn't
run into any trouble.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, let's shut down
those transporters
and start that diagnostic
we've been putting off.
Sir, are you sure
we shouldn't wait
for the Captain to get back?
Ensign Kim, you have been given
a direct order.
Do as the Commander
tells you.
Aye, sir.
Have you finished upgrading
the internal sensors, Ensign?
I'm working on it, sir.
( door opens )
I hope so.
Wait here.
Is something wrong, sir?
No. It's just
tomorrow's duty roster.
Sir, Captain Janeway's shuttle
has gone to warp.
CHAKOTAY:
Thank you, Tuvok.
Chakotay to all hands.
Let's do it.
Sir?
KIM:
Red Alert!
Security to the Bridge!
You're wasting your time, Harry.
All my teams
have taken control
of Security, Engineering
and all key systems.
You'll never get away with this.
People will fight back.
That's going to be
a little difficult.
All your off-duty Starfleet
friends have been locked down,
in quarters.
( yelling )
( grunting )
I guess you've made
your choice.
Jonas to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
They're putting up a fight
on Deck 2.
We could use some help.
Carlson, O'Donnell,
get these people
to the brig.
Ayala, take the conn
and move us
out of com range
of Janeway's shuttle.
You're with me.
Deck 2.
Thanks for watching
my back in there.
Right.
Are you okay?
To tell you
the truth, uh...
shooting Harry...
got me a little rattled.
He's only stunned.
We're not going to
kill anybody today,
unless it's
absolutely necessary.
Just stay close.
Stay low.
They've got us
pinned down.
We'll just have to shoot
our way past them.
Ready?
Seska!
It's just like
old times, isn't it?
CHAKOTAY:
Thanks for the help.
We've got to get moving.
Some of Janeway's people
are trying to set up a command
center in the Mess Hall.
( crew shouting )
I wouldn't do that
if I were you.
This phaser's set
on wide beam.
I could take you all
in one shot.
Everybody drop
your weapons.
( weapons clattering )
You heard the man.
Drop your weapons.
( more weapons clattering )
Don't look so surprised,
Commander.
I know a winner
when I see one.
I'm with you.
Do you want me to shoot him?
We're still going to need
a cook.
Chakotay
to Engineering.
What's your status?
MALE:
Engineering is secure.
Transporter Rooms 1 and 2,
status.
MALE 2:
Transporter Room 1
is under control.
FEMALE:
Transporter Room 2 is secure.
Shuttle Bay, status.
MALE 3:
Shuttle Bay is secured,
Commander.
I'll take care
of the prisoners here.
You two get some help and
start rounding up the personnel
that are still locked
down in quarters.
Bring them to Cargo Bay 1.
We did it.
Just like old times.
You did a good job today.
Thanks.
Just make sure
you keep it up.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It means I'm not as easy
to win over as Chakotay.
Come on! Let's go.
Wait here.
Seska, what's going on?
Move it.
Why are we being
treated like prisoners?
No talking.
Over there,
with the rest of them.
What are you going
to do with us?
I said no talking!
Hey, hey, hey, take it easy.
I told you
it was a mistake
letting Starfleet
people in on this.
Now's not the time,
Seska.
Take a good look around you.
You're under armed guard.
You may also notice that your
senior officers aren't here.
They're in the brig.
They'll be put off the ship
at the first habitable planet
we come to.
All except Janeway and Paris...
who will arrive
at their rendezvous coordinates
to find
that Voyager's not there.
In short,
I've taken control of the ship.
I don't blame any of you
for the mistakes
of your leaders.
So I'm giving you
a choice.
You can be put off the ship
with your superiors,
or you can do what Neelix
and some of your
other crew members
have already done,
and join me.
If you do,
you'll be part of a crew
that's going to do whatever
it takes to get us home
as fast as possible.
Under my command,
we won't let almighty
Federation principles
get in the way of opportunities,
the way Janeway did
when she destroyed the Array
that could've gotten us home.
And we won't be wasting
precious time,
stopping to investigate
every insignificant anomaly
that we come across.
What we will do...
is use any means necessary
to acquire technology
that can shorten our journey.
To hell
with Starfleet regulations.
You have 15 minutes
to make up your minds.
PARIS:
B'Elanna.
What's going on here?
Computer, freeze program.
Are you in the habit
of just walking in
on people's private
holodeck time?
It's not as if I caught you
dancing the rumba
with a naked Bolian.
We had a lunch date,
remember?
Is it lunchtime
already?
I must've lost track
of the time.
Well, I expected
to find you
shooting pool at Sandrine's,
not hanging out with Seska.
What sort of program
is this, anyway?
It's really something.
I was doing a routine purge
of the database--
you know, taking out old files
that were taking up space--
and I found this holonovel.
It's a kind of "what if" story
all about a Maquis mutiny.
It's completely compelling...
and believable.
I guess it's because
it's all about us.
Who wrote it?
Now that...
is the big mystery.
Whoever the author is
has gone to a lot of trouble
to keep his
identity a secret.
It's been encrypted.
Why do you suppose someone would
try so hard to be anonymous?
Well, think about it.
Whoever plays this program
takes on the role of
a Starfleet Security Officer
who gets approached
by Chakotay
to help the Maquis
take over the ship.
I mean, it's pretty
inflammatory.
You think we should
tell the Captain?
Probably.
It would be pretty hard for us
to give her a full report,
if we don't know
how the story ends.
Excellent point.
Great. Can you
reset it for me?
You?! I was just getting
to the good part.
Oh, come on, B'Elanna,
be a sport.
I've got to be back on duty
in less than an hour.
Besides, isn't half
the fun of a holonovel
having someone
to talk it over with?
All right.
You owe me one.
Where are you headed?
The Bridge.
Mind if I walk with you?
I was kind of
hoping you would.
So how's it going?
Couldn't be better.
Tuvok still giving
you a hard time?
Doesn't he always?
I don't know about you,
but when I think
about spending 70 years
on the same ship with that guy,
it gives me a headache.
Not to mention
an upset stomach.
Bridge.
I hear you're
planning a mutiny.
Computer,
halt turbolift.
Who told you that?
Let's just say there are rumors.
( laughs )
Yeah, well, don't believe
everything you hear.
Of course not.
I just wanted you to know
that whatever happens,
I'm with you.
Computer, resume turbolift.
I'm serious.
Just tell me what
you want me to do.
All right, Ensign,
here it is.
As soon as the Captain
leaves to meet the Rukani,
I want you to put all crew
quarters on lockdown.
I'll ask you if you've finished
upgrading the internal sensors.
If you say yes,
I'll know we're ready to go.
I understand.
I'm watching you.
No tricks.
We are entering
the Rukani sector, Commander.
Inform the Captain.
Aye, sir.
Well, Commander...  Voyager's
all yours.
There's a first time
for everything, I guess.
Don't worry, Captain.
I'll keep your ship
safe and sound.
I'm sure you will.
PARIS:
Shuttle Bay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Mr. Paris.
The shuttle's ready to go,
whenever you are.
JANEWAY:
On my way.
Captain,
I've been thinking.
Are you sure you don't want to
take Lieutenant Tuvok with you,
just in case
the Rukani turn out
to be less friendly
than they seem?
I assure you, Commander,
I have made
thorough preparations
for the Captain's safety
during her away mission.
You, on the other hand,
are still adapting
to your duties
as First Officer.
Under the circumstances,
I believe my time
will be better spent
assisting you in your effort
to justify the trust
the Captain has placed in you.
I appreciate your concern
for my safety, Mr. Chakotay,
but Tuvok's right.
Lieutenant Paris and
I will be just fine.
I'll see you
in 24 hours.
Lieutenant,
I want you to keep close tabs
on the Captain's shuttle.
Let's make sure she doesn't
run into any trouble.
Aye, sir.
Ensign, let's shut down
the transporters
and start that diagnostic
we've been putting off.
Sir, are you sure
we shouldn't wait
for the Captain
to get back?
TUVOK:
Ensign Kim,
you have been given
a direct order.
Do as the Commander tells you.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
Have you finished upgrading
the internal sensors?
Yes, sir.
I hope so.
Wait here.
Is anything wrong,
sir?
No. It's just
tomorrow's duty roster.
The Captain's shuttle
has gone to warp.
Thank you, Tuvok.
Chakotay to all hands. Let's do
it.
Sir?
Tuvok, get down!
I guess you've
made your choice.
It's not over yet,
Chakotay.
Take them all
to the brig.
Sir, we have
to do something.
What did you have
in mind, Ensign?
Escape,
retake the ship.
We will indeed
attempt to do so,
when the time is right.
What about
trying it now?
Such a foolhardy proposal
suggests a lack
of proper training.
Need I remind you
that we are confined
behind an electrostatic
force field?
We can't just sit
here and do nothing.
We are hardly
doing nothing.
We are observing
the enemy, watching for
any discernible patterns
in their procedures,
looking for any weakness
in their defenses.
How long is this observing
business going to take?
It's been over an hour already.
I'm getting bored.
I am not concerned with
your amusement, Ensign.
We are in a crisis situation
and we will follow procedure
and procedure dictates
that we wait
for the right opportunity
to attempt an escape
whether it takes
an hour or a week.
A week?!
Who wrote this stuff?
Hold Kim and Tuvok here.
Bring the rest of them
to Cargo Bay 1.
Enjoy the wait.
...and we won't be wasting
precious time
stopping to investigate
every insignificant anomaly
we come across.
What we will do is use
any means necessary
to acquire technology that
can shorten our journey.
To hell with
Starfleet regulations.
You have 15 minutes
to make up your minds.
I don't need 15 minutes.
I'm with you right now.
So, by the time I
got around to joining
Chakotay's band of rebels...
Uh-huh.
he was so suspicious
of my motives
that he assigned
me to lubricate
the warp plasma
manifolds.
You should've tried
going along with the mutiny
from the beginning.
It's much more fun.
Oh, believe me,
next time I will.
I couldn't help
overhearing.
You two are talking
about the new holonovel.
I tried sending
an encoded message
to Captain Janeway's shuttle,
to warn her about the mutiny,
but Chakotay caught me,
phasered me,
and the program reset.
Next time, I'm going to pretend
to go along
with the conspirators,
and then stage
a counterstrike.
I thought we were
going to keep this
our little secret.
Don't look at me.
I didn't tell him.
I heard about it
from the Doctor.
The Doctor?
I may have let it slip
while I was running
his weekly diagnostic.
Oh, great.
Who else knows about it?
Don't worry about me.
My lips are sealed.
So what's this Ayala tells
me about a new holonovel?
Get in line, Harry.
PARIS:
Lieutenant Paris's Personal
Log, Stardate 50953.4.
I've decided to take
B'Elanna's advice
and replay the holonovel,
this time,
as a full-fledged member
of Chakotay's
team of mutineers.
I hope it turns out
better than before.
Where the hell are
those warp engines?
They're still off-line.
We can't seem to get the
dilithium matrix reinitialized.
It's been two days.
Don't worry.
B'Elanna's on it.
Run a full
security sweep.
Something tells me there's
more to this engine problem
than a faulty
dilithium matrix.
You think we've got
a saboteur on board?
There's a ship approaching,
bearing 216 mark 33.
It's Janeway's shuttle.
Open a channel.
Hello, Kathryn.
How did it go
with the Rukani?
You're out of uniform,
Commander.
There have been
a few changes
since you've been gone.
So I've heard.
You think I don't have
any friends left on Voyager?
Apparently, you do,
but I'll find them.
And then what?
Will you kill them
or just put them off the ship?
( sighs heavily )
Nobody has to die here today.
I thought you were
a man of your word, Chakotay.
I guess I was mistaken.
I'm sorry
it had to come to this,
but the crew believes I can get
them home faster than you can.
It's going to be
a little difficult
without warp engines,
isn't it?
Our warp drive may be
temporarily off-line,
but our weapon systems
are fully operational.
They're powering phasers.
Kathryn, don't try to be a hero.
I've been reasonable so far.
I'll allow you
to keep the shuttle.
I'll even transport you
some extra provisions,
but if you don't stand down,
I will destroy your shuttle.
You've just threatened
the wrong woman, Chakotay.
What does she think she's
going to accomplish?
We can obliterate them
in one shot.
Not till I
give the order.
Reopen a channel.
I don't know how, but they've
disabled our shields.
We're completely vulnerable.
Target their warp
core and fire.
I always said
Janeway was a fool.
COMPUTER:
Intruder alert on Deck 8.
It's Paris and Janeway.
Janeway's no fool.
She tricked us
into destroying her shuttle,
then transported over
while the shields were down!
She's trying
to free the prisoners.
You've got the Bridge.
You're with me.
Get away from that panel!
( groans )
Oh!
Drop it.
Computer, resume program.
COMPUTER:
The holographic simulation
has ended.
Well, start it up again,
right where it left off.
Unable to comply.
Why not?
Additional narrative parameters
have not been programmed.
Are you saying
there's no more story?
Affirmative.
This is someone's idea
of a practical joke, right?
Please rephrase the question.
There.
I've bypassed
the security override.
Try it now.
Computer,
identify the author
of holographic
program entitled
"Insurrection Alpha."
COMPUTER:
That information is classified.
I've tried every decryption
protocol I can think of.
Whoever wrote this is good.
Not to mention
sadistic.
I can't believe we've been
left hanging like this.
Any luck?
( both sighing )
Me, neither.
I've discreetly
questioned everybody
I thought I could trust.
Either nobody knows,
or nobody's talking.
Remember the good old days
when it was impossible
to keep a secret
on a ship this small?
Well, if that takes care
of our official agenda,
there's another matter
I'd like to discuss.
Commander Chakotay informs me
there's a new holonovel
that's become quite
popular among the crew.
It's been accessed
47 times
by 33 different
crew members.
I don't suppose anyone here
is familiar
with what we're talking about.
Actually, uh, Captain,
I'm the one who found it
on the auxiliary database.
I've been
running it too.
Anybody else?
I understand that the author
of this little opus
has chosen to remain anonymous,
perhaps because
of the controversial nature
of the story,
which depicts Commander Chakotay
as the leader of
a Maquis mutiny.
Well, now that the cat's
out of the bag...
I want each of you
to talk to your staff
and find out
who our anonymous author is.
That won't be necessary,
Captain.
I am the author
of the program in question.
You, Tuvok?
I never knew
you had literary aspirations.
Not to mention talent.
What a story.
I'm afraid there's been
a misunderstanding.
The program
is not a holonovel.
It is
a tactical training scenario.
When you first invited
the Maquis to join our crew,
I believed that mutiny
was a very real possibility.
With that in mind, I began to
write a training program
for junior security officers
to prepare them
for such an eventuality.
But you never finished it.
No. As the two crews
began to work together,
I concluded that
the threat of an insurrection
was increasingly unlikely.
I realized the program itself
might exacerbate
the very conflict
I sought to avoid.
Therefore,
I deleted the scenario.
Or so I believed.
Apparently,
you didn't account for
B'Elanna's exceptional
computer skills.
Nor her somewhat
excessive curiosity.
I apologize for
my carelessness, Captain.
Forget your
carelessness.
What you should be
apologizing for
is leaving us all
hanging by a thread.
You've got to finish
the story.
On the contrary, Mr. Paris,
the program has the potential
to incite animosity
among the crew
and must be
permanently deleted.
I have no doubt
the Captain concurs.
With all due respect,
Mr. Tuvok, loosen up.
You may have intended
this program
to be
a tactical training tool,
but it looks to me
like it's turned into
a bit of harmless fun.
As the Captain of this ship,
surely you must--
I'm more than just
a Captain.
I'm the leader of a community,
and communities need
entertainment, culture,
creative outlets.
Since we're not exactly privy
to every new piece
of music or holonovel
that's written back home,
I think it's only natural
that we should start
creating our own.
Besides, Tuvok, if the crew
doesn't get an ending,
you may have a real mutiny
on your hands.
( both laughing )
If Tuvok doesn't want
to finish the story,
I volunteer.
Oh?
I've always wanted to
write a holonovel.
I think I could make
it pretty exciting.
Good. Then it's settled.
I, for one, can't wait to see
if Captain Janeway
manages to outwit
the conspirators.
Well, if it isn't
Mr. Anonymous.
Come to check up
on your replacement?
Since the Captain
insists on allowing you
to proceed with this
frivolous exercise,
I thought you
might benefit
from the original
probability studies
I conducted before
beginning the scenario.
Well, thanks, Tuvok,
but I don't need
any probability studies.
I'm just sort of making it up
as I go along.
Indeed.
I'd be curious to know
what you've "made up" thus far.
Well, I was thinking,
Paris and Janeway
retake the ship,
and then she decides to execute
all the conspirators.
That is an entirely implausible
plot development.
Captain Janeway
would never behave
in such an inhumane manner.
This isn't real life, Tuvok,
it's fiction.
Don't get so caught up
in logic.
Logic is an integral part
of narrative structure.
According to the
"Dictates of Poetics,"
by T'Hain of Vulcan,
a character's actions
must flow inexorably
from his or her
established traits.
Well, I don't know anything
about T'Hain,
but I do know what makes
an interesting story,
and that's
unexpected plot twists.
If you think
I will allow you
to turn this program into a
parody, you are sorely mistaken.
Are you saying that you're going
to finish it yourself?
Artistic
differences?
I would hardly call
Mr. Paris's ideas... artistic.
Apparently,
my instincts don't comply
with the Vulcan
"Dictates of Poetics."
Well, I've got a couple
of suggestions that might help.
Now, up until now, the story's
been nothing but action,
which is fine,
but what it needs
is a little heart,
a little emotion.
We are not writing
a romance novel, Lieutenant.
"We"?
I've decided that your efforts
would benefit
from my collaboration.
Oh, really?
Listen, I don't care which one
of you is writing this thing.
All I'm saying is that there
is room in every good story
for a little bit of passion.
You know,
maybe you're on to something.
I could add a steamy love scene
between the Starfleet
conn officer
and the Maquis engineer.
Oh, that's realistic.
How about a fresh pot
of coffee
to keep those
creative juices flowing, huh?
Thanks, Neelix.
Uh, while I'm here...
Uh, let me guess.
You have a suggestion to make.
Of course not.
I would never presume
to interfere
in the creative process.
More of a comment, really,
about the Neelix character--
How surprising.
He would never betray
the Captain
the way he does in that story.
No offense, Mr. Vulcan,
but I don't think
you understand
my character very well.
Tuvok, did you
forget to follow
the "Dictates of Poetics"?
Perhaps we should find someplace
quieter to work.
Now, that's the first
intelligent suggestion
I've heard all evening.
I believe our
first step should be
to create a carefully
constructed outline
of the remaining chapters.
I told you, Tuvok.
I'm just making
it up as I go.
We cannot proceed without
a carefully constructed outline.
There you go with
that "we" stuff again.
I don't remember agreeing
to let you help me.
Need I remind you that it was
I who first began the scenario.
And you think
I'm compromising
your creative vision?
In so many words, yes.
And it is my duty to insure
that ship security
is not compromised
by your creative vision.
You had your chance
to finish this story
and you wanted
to delete it.
True, but since that is
no longer an option,
I am now exercising
my prerogative
as the original author.
Look, Tuvok...
for the last time,
I don't need any help.
DOCTOR:
Ah, there you are.
I have several
brilliant ideas
for upcoming chapters
of your holonovel,
as well as a list of revisions
and dialogue changes
that I believe will improve
the earlier installments.
I don't believe this.
No thanks are necessary.
In addition, I'm prepared
to offer my expertise
in the creation
of holographic mise-en-scène.
Computer, override
the EMH program's
autonomous controls, and
transfer him back to Sick Bay.
Now, wait just a minute...
( sighs )
Thanks, Tuvok.
Now that I think
about it...
I'll take it from here.
You may find that difficult,
since I'm the only one
who can make additions
to the program.
( chuckling )
All right,
Tuvok, you win.
We'll finish the
story together.
That is a very rational
decision, Mr. Paris.
Computer, reinitiate
the holographic program
entitled "Insurrection Alpha."
Security clearance:
Tuvok-four-seven-seven-four.
COMPUTER:
The program
has been reinitiated.
The first thing we're going
to change is that title.
Reformat the holo-matrix
for the addition of new
interactive algorithms.
The holo-matrix
has been formatted.
Reopen the narrative
parameters file.
Captain, we just lost power
in both transporter rooms.
The com went down,
and the holodeck systems
are completely scrambled.
What are we doing in the brig?
I have no idea.
We haven't given the
computer instructions
to create a location yet.
SESKA: Hello, Tuvok.
I've been expecting you.
If you can see me,
you've obviously reopened
the narrative parameters file
of the tactical scenario
you've been working on.
How do you know that? You're a
hologram.
SESKA:
That's right.
A holographic representation
of Seska,
one of the Maquis
shipmates you betrayed.
I would've thought all
that time you spent
spying on us
might've given you
a little more insight
into the Maquis,
but after looking over
what you've already written,
I can see you need
a little help.
So I've created
this representation of myself
to guide you through the rest
of the program.
There is no more program.
There is now.
I finished writing it for you
with a few revisions of my own.
Revisions?
To start with,
the holodeck is now sealed.
Your friends will find it
very difficult
to get you
out of here.
And the safety protocols
are off,
which means if I shoot you,
and I am going to shoot you,
you'll die.
But not just yet.
( console beeping )
You've got ten seconds to run.
Nine, eight...
Computer, end program.
...seven, six...
Holodeck 1 to Bridge.
...five...
Emergency transport.
Oh, did I forget to tell you?
The moment you restarted
the program,
the com system went down.
Four... three...
I guess we better do
what she says.
...two, one...
You should never have
crossed her, Tuvok.
"She" has been dead
for over a year now.
There would've been no way to
predict this turn of events.
We should've known
Seska wouldn't let
a thing like death
stop her from getting even.
JANEWAY:
Tuvok, Tom.
In here.
Captain.
We're going to have
to transport to the Cargo Bay
to free the rest
of the prisoners.
It's safer than trying
to make it on foot.
She's a hologram too.
Apparently, she believes
we're here
to help her retake the ship
from the mutineers.
I say we play along.
We could use all the help
we can get against Seska.
You're forgetting it was Seska
who rewrote the scenario.
For all we know,
she's programmed
Captain Janeway
to betray us.
I suppose you have
a better idea?
The safest course of action
is to avoid
participation of any kind.
Eventually, the real Captain
will discover our predicament,
and shut down the program
from the outside.
Let's move.
CHAKOTAY:
Hold it right there.
Back off.
Or what? You'll shoot us?
Go right ahead.
Whatever you say.
( gasping )
SESKA:
Poor Kathryn.
I guess nobody told her
the phaser rifles
from Storage Locker 3
have been malfunctioning.
You're an incredible
woman, Seska.
You see who's in charge
now, don't you?
So if I were you,
I'd get moving again.
The program's not over.
We have no intention
of participating
in this exercise.
You don't want to end up
like your Captain, do you?
You programmed all this.
The malfunctioning phaser,
a version of Chakotay
who's attracted to you...
None of it's real.
You hear that?
He thinks this is a game.
Show him he's wrong.
I've been waiting
a long time for this.
( groans )
Next time,
you'll believe me
when I tell you
the safety protocols are off.
Now, you've got
five seconds
to start running again,
or you'll end up
with more than
a flesh wound.
So much for not playing
along with Seska's program.
Are you able to continue?
I'll keep up.
The question is:
Where are we going?
I have an idea.
What's the point? This isn't the
real Sick Bay.
I may be able to use
some of this
holographic equipment
to treat your wound.
Besides, it's as good a place
as any to hide from Seska.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
No emergency, Doc. I'm fine.
Nonsense. You have second-degree
phaser burns. Please have a seat
on bio-bed one.
That's all right, Doc. I'm
telling you, I feel fine.
You require treatment.
20 cc's nitric acid.
( screams )
A little proverbial
salt in the wound.
You're looking well.
Go!
I'm not going
to leave you.
It was a pleasure treating you.
Don't hesitate to call again.
Are you all right,
Mr. Paris?
Oh, just great.
Maybe we can go to
the Mess Hall now,
and let the holographic Neelix
burn my arm with a frying pan.
Your feeble attempt at wit
notwithstanding,
it does appear that Seska
has reprogrammed
the holographic crew
to torture us.
I suggest we avoid
meeting any more of them.
Seska to Tuvok.
I know you can hear me.
Oh, terrific.
I just wanted to remind you
that wherever you go,
I'll find you.
I say we try
the Jefferies tubes.
I concur.
Captain, you're not
going to believe this,
but Seska caused these
cascade failures.
Seska? How?
What she lacked in loyalty,
she made up for in ingenuity.
According to the backup
computer logs,
she got into Tuvok's scenario
on stardate 48671,
about a month before
she left the ship.
She programmed it to cause
all of these shutdowns
the next time Tuvok reopened
the narrative parameters file,
which he didn't do
until today.
Can we get them out?
Seska laid booby-trapped
subroutines everywhere.
If we try to open
the holodeck doors,
the power grid
is rigged to explode.
And the transporters
are still off-line.
You said the narrative
parameters file is open now.
Seska's revised program
is playing out as we speak.
If Seska can rewrite Tuvok...
maybe I can rewrite Seska.
So, Tuvok, anything
in the "Dictates of Poetics"
about how to escape
from a ship full
of insane holograms?
Your attempts at humor
are hardly constructive,
Mr. Paris.
( beeping denial )
The controls are jammed.
I cannot close
the hatch.
Tuvok!
Where do you suppose
this came from?
That is an intriguing question.
You think Seska's
toying with us?
Taking us to the brink
of death again,
then letting us live,
so she can keep
torturing us?
I prefer a more optimistic
interpretation.
It is possible our shipmates
outside the holodeck
have learned
of our predicament
and have found
a way to help us
by making additions
to the program,
such as
that plasma extinguisher.
If you want to look
on the bright side,
I'm certainly not going
to argue with you.
If they do know
what's going on,
why just hand us
a plasma extinguisher?
Why not shut down
the hologrid
or change the scenario?
I would imagine Seska
has made it very difficult
for anyone to implement
more than minor changes.
Take a look at this.
( alarm buzzing )
You were right.
We must follow
their instructions.
Hello, boys.
What do you say we go
for a little walk?
Where did they come from?
Seska's program is
adding new algorithms
to counteract the
changes we're making.
I need more access
to the narrative subroutines.
I can't get in.
You better find a way.
Otherwise, Tom and Tuvok
aren't going to make it
out of there alive.
It looks like
Chakotay's taking them
to the holographic cargo bay.
Torres to Kim. How are you
coming with those transporters?
Seska's program has completely
disabled the relay access ports.
It's going to take a while to
get Tom and Tuvok out of there.
I guess that means
I keep writing.
As you can see, the last of your
comrades have been captured.
In case anybody had any doubts,
it should be obvious by now
that this is no longer
a Starfleet vessel.
Bring Paris and Tuvok
over here.
You and you,
bring your weapons.
CHAKOTAY: What are you doing?
What do you think I'm doing?
I'm going to execute them
right here, right now.
I need access to
the character algorithms now.
I'm on it.
Fire on my order.
Belay that.
What are you doing?
We planned this.
I'm not sure
it's necessary to kill them.
If I'm not mistaken,
the Chakotay hologram
is undergoing some sort
of character change.
Do you think they're trying
to help us again?
These two rodents betrayed us.
They deserve to die.
Don't listen to her, Commander.
You've taken the ship.
There is no need to add murder
to your list of offenses.
Quiet!
Lower your weapons.
It's working.
Now, if I can just keep
modifying the Chakotay
hologram...
SESKA:
You're not going
to lose your nerve, are you?
We have what we want.
There's no reason
to kill them.
Prepare to fire on my order!
CHAKOTAY:
Seska, I'm in command
of this operation.
Not anymore!
I don't believe it.
The program is reconfiguring
the sub-processors
to counter every change we make.
No matter what we do,
it rewrites itself
so that Tom and Tuvok
will die.
I'm not out of ideas yet.
Is there anyone else who
wants to challenge my authority?
Isn't their loyalty inspiring?
Set your phasers
to "kill."
Don't listen to her.
Fire on my order.
What the hell was that?
Don't move, Seska.
FEMALE:
Bridge to Seska.
We're under attack
by the Rukani.
The Rukani?
The people the Captain
and I were visiting
while you were busy
taking over the ship.
When we realized there was
a mutiny in progress,
we called them
for a little assistance.
Harry, have you got
transporters yet?
KIM:
Still working on it, Captain.
You're not getting
this ship back.
That is a rather bold statement
for someone in your position.
Computer, initiate 60-second
self-destruct sequence.
Authorization: zeta-one.
COMPUTER:
This ship will self-destruct
in 60 seconds.
Computer,
belay that order.
Authorization: Tuvok-
four-seven-seven-four.
Unable to comply.
Voiceprint not recognized.
If you don't hand over
that phaser rifle,
everyone on this ship
is going to be dead in--
Self-destruct in 45 seconds.
I don't know how
she rigged it, Captain,
but when she ordered
the self-destruct,
it initiated an overload
in the holodeck power relays.
The whole grid is going to blow.
Self-destruct in 30 seconds.
Hand over the weapon,
or the ship
is going to be destroyed.
I have set this phaser
to kill.
If you do not deactivate
the self-destruct sequence,
I will fire.
I'm surprised at you, Tuvok.
That's not very logical.
If I'm dead, who'll turn off
the self-destruct?
Fifteen seconds
to self-destruct.
Thirteen... 12... 11...
ten... nine...
Computer, terminate
self-destruct sequence.
Authorization: zeta-one.
Self-destruct sequence
has been terminated.
Now call off
your Rukani friends.
Do what she says.
Tuvok--
That's an order,
Mr. Paris.
Paris to the Rukani vessel.
Thank you for your assistance,
but everything's
under control now.
It is, isn't it?
I guess, if you
want something done right,
you've got to do it yourself.
( screaming )
Not bad.
Seska's not
the only one
who knows how to cause
a phaser malfunction.
COMPUTER:
The holographic simulation
has ended.
It's over.
Kim to Engineering.
I think I can give you
transporters now, Captain.
That's all right, Harry.
No rush.
Here's to stories
with happy endings.
( light laughter )
I must say, Captain,
causing the alien ship
to come to our aid
was a very effective
plot development.
Who says deus ex machina
is an outdated literary device?
I'm just glad you didn't
come down with
a case of writer's block.
So, you two are going to
have to come up with
a new idea for your next
literary collaboration.
What about doing a Western?
Or a detective story.
I don't care
what kind of story it is,
as long as I'm not
the bad guy this time.
( laughter )
I've got a great idea
for a holonovel
about a daring trader
who becomes a cook
on a starship.
Eventually, he rises--
Mr. Neelix...
if Mr. Paris and I do create
another work of holofiction,
I assure you,
we will choose a subject
much less close to home.
( laughter )