( ominous theme playing )
COLLECTIVE:
We are the Borg.
Existence as you know it
is over.
We will add your biological
and technological
distinctiveness to our own.
Resistance is...
( electronic crackling )
( theme music playing )
MALE:
The cardinal...is a thief.
I delivered two portraits
of his mindless nephew
more than three months ago
to be depicted
in the heroic mode
of an Hercules or an Achilles.
So specified our contract.
I complied...
making that young fool
of a nephew
look far more heroic
than nature ever intended,
an act on my part far greater
than anything accomplished
by Hercules or Achilles.
And what have I,
the divine Leonardo da Vinci,
received in payment?
The cardinal's
eternal gratitude?
Ha-ha!
Esatto!
In other words, signorina...
less than nothing.
All the more reason why
you should accept my proposal.
Money is beside the point,
signo-- Catarina, is it?
Yes. I'm only asking for
a corner, one bench--
A place to work
on my own projects...
paintings, sculptures.
Just being here
in your company
is inspiring to me.
Flattery, Catarina,
is also beside the point.
Besides, I prefer
my solitude. Scusami.
( machinery whirring )
( laughs )
Meraviglioso.
What will you
call it?
"The Arm of Hephaestus."
The god of the forge.
Every blacksmith who
has ever swung a hammer
will thank me
for this creation.
Someone once said:
"All invention
is but an extension
of the body of man."
Do not think
that just because I have
enjoyed your visit today,
that I am prepared
to turn my workshop
into a traveler's inn.
Che cazzo!
Here, let me
help you.
You will get your hands
covered in goose grease.
It's good
for the skin.
DA VINCI:
Let us see if we can find
his big brother.
Hopefully,
he will be stronger.
( church bells ringing )
This looks like
a flying machine.
I thought that
because my imagination
took flight so easily,
my body could do the same.
I was wrong.
It's this...
flapping approach.
You've designed your machine
to mimic the way
a bat or a sparrow flies.
Yes, yes. So?
So what if you based it...
on the hawk instead?
The hawk.
A creature that
glides through the air.
Esatto.
We will design
a new machine...
and, you, Catarina,
will help me fly it.
I'll need someplace to work.
A corner?
One workbench?
That will be fine.
( laughing )
Ten scudi a week,
and you provide
your own materials.
Seven...
and I might need to borrow
a few things on occasion.
Then we have an agreement.
( com-link beeps )
CHAKOTAY:
Chakotay to Janeway.
Go ahead.
Captain, we need you
in Engineering.
There's something here
you should see.
On my way.
Computer, end program.
What have you got?
CHAKOTAY:
Some bad news.
The long-range probe
we sent out two months ago
has stopped transmitting.
I thought it was a problem with
the communications grid,
then I cleared up the last few
seconds of telemetry.
Take a look at this.
( console beeping )
This could be it,
Captain.
Borg space.
We don't know exactly
how many vessels are out there,
but their space
appears to be vast.
It includes thousands
of solar systems--
all Borg.
We are, no doubt, entering
the heart of their territory.
There's no going around it.
But there may be a way
through it.
Before the probe was disabled,
it picked up
a narrow corridor of space
devoid of Borg activity.
We've nicknamed it
"The Northwest Passage."
Unfortunately,
the passage is filled with
intense
gravimetric distortions
probably caused by a string
of quantum singularities.
Better to ride the rapids
than face the hive.
Exactly. We're going
to set a course
for that corridor
and go into full tactical alert.
Where do we stand with weapons?
I have reprogrammed
the phaser banks
to a rotating modulation,
but I suspect the Borg
will adapt quickly.
We can use every edge.
Ensign?
I've already configured
the long-range sensors
to scan for transwarp
signatures--
an early-warning
system.
Good work.
Doctor, how are you coming
on the medical front?
I've analyzed every
square millimeter
of the Borg corpse
we recovered three months ago.
I'm closer to understanding
how their assimilation
technology works,
and I might
be able to create
some sort of medical defense.
Redouble your efforts.
This is your top priority.
Neelix, I doubt we can
resupply the ship any time soon.
No problem, sir.
I'm working on a plan
to extend our food
and replicator rations.
We have to act fast.
The Borg have captured
one of our probes.
They know we're out here.
We'll do everything
in our power
to avoid a direct
confrontation,
but, if and when
we do engage the Borg,
I'm confident
that we'll be ready.
I have faith in each
and every one of you.
Let's do it.
( dramatic theme playing )
( people chattering orders
indistinctly )
Coming through.
Open!
I want to cut down the time
it takes to seal off the decks.
In case we take on
some uninvited guests.
Exactly. And I want
to increase the magnitude
of the force fields.
These injection tubules
are the first step
in the Borg
assimilation process.
Once inside the skin,
they release
a series of nanoprobes
into the bloodstream.
Maybe we can
develop some type of
protective shielding
against them.
Unlikely.
The tubules are capable
of penetrating
any known alloy
or energy field...
which means our battle
must be waged
inside the body itself.
The first tissue to be
attacked by the nanoprobes
is the victim's blood.
Assimilation
is almost instantaneous.
They take over
the blood cell functions,
like a virus.
Which suggests to me
that we should try
to enhance
the immune system.
Create an "assimilation
antibody," as it were.
I doubt we can actually
destroy the nanoprobes,
but we might be able
to slow them down.
( PADD beeps )
Let's try a submicron
dissection on the probes
we've collected so far,
see if we can discover
the assimilation mechanism.
( PADD continues beeping )
( ominous theme playing )
Kes, is
something wrong?
Kes.
I saw Borg.
You've had a
telepathic experience?
There were bodies...
dozens of them dead.
How's Kes?
Unsettled and uncertain.
Over the past two hours,
she has experienced
several telepathic visions
about the death of Borg
and the destruction of Voyager.
Some sort of premonitions?
Possibly.
We can't just ignore
her intuition,
but I see no reason
to alter our plan.
Tuvok, I want you
to keep an eye on her--
Captain...
long-range sensors
are picking up
transwarp signatures...
5.8 light-years
distant...
closing from behind.
Red Alert.
JANEWAY:
Evasive maneuvers.
( rumbling )
What's happening?
We've dropped out of warp.
Bridge to Engineering.
What's going on down there?
TORRES:
I'm not sure, Captain.
Some kind of subspace turbulence
is preventing us
from creating
a stable warp field.
Turbulence is increasing.
I'm reading two Borg vessels.
Make that three.
Four.
No, five.
Fifteen Borg vessels.
Distance--
2.1 light-years and closing.
Shields to maximum.
Stand by all weapons.
They're in visual range.
JANEWAY:
On screen.
( suspenseful theme playing )
My God.
Captain...
KIM:
I'm picking up
a polaron beam.
We're being scanned.
Think good thoughts.
The last cube
has rejoined the others.
Did we sustain any damage?
KIM:
No. Shields held.
Warp engines are
coming back on line.
All primary systems
are stable.
Stand down Red Alert.
Harry...maintain
a long-range sensor lock
on that Borg armada.
They seemed to be in quite
a hurry, didn't they?
I'd like to know
what they're up to.
KIM:
Yes, ma'am.
JANEWAY:
I'll take this near-miss
as a good omen.
Resume our course,
Mr. Paris.
If we needed
any more evidence
that we've entered
Borg space,
I think we just got it.
I'll be in my ready room.
( door chimes )
Yes. Come in.
We've just completed
the latest sensor sweep.
So far, so good.
The Northwest Passage
is still clear
of Borg activity.
I'd like to see
a tactical update.
According to
my calculations,
neither of us has eaten
since last night.
Join me for dinner?
No, thanks.
I'm not hungry.
I've got a lot of work to do.
I see.
I've been looking through
the personal log entries
of all the Starfleet Captains
who encountered the Borg.
I've gone over every engagement,
from the moment
Q flung the Enterprise
into the path of that first cube
to the massacre at Wolf 359.
Every battle,
every skirmish,
anything that might
give me an insight
into the mind of the Collective.
And?
In the words
of Jean-Luc Picard...
"In their Collective state,
"the Borg are utterly
without mercy,
"driven by one will alone--
the will to conquer.
They are beyond redemption,
beyond reason."
And then there's Captain Amasov
of the Endeavor.
"It is my opinion that the Borg
are as close to pure evil
as any race we've ever
encountered..."
( chuckles )
What's so funny?
Uh, nothing.
You're smiling.
Obviously, I've said
something amusing.
You sounded
just like Amasov.
What?
Just now, while you
were reading his log,
you were using
his inflections.
I did not.
Yes, you were.
And before that, you were
doing a pretty good Picard.
Was I?
It's nothing to be
ashamed about,
echoing the greats.
Ensign Hickman
in Astrophysics
does a passable Janeway.
If we manage to survive
the next few days,
I'm going to have a little
chat with Ensign Hickman.
Imitating the Captain, huh?
Surely that violates some kind
of Starfleet protocol.
This day was inevitable.
We all knew it,
and we've all tried
to prepare ourselves
for the challenge ahead.
But at what point
is the risk too great?
At what point do we come about
and retreat to
friendly territory?
Could the crew
accept living out
the rest of their lives
in the Delta Quadrant?
I keep looking
to all these Captains,
my comrades in arms.
But the truth is...
I'm alone.
If that moment comes...
we'll face it together,
and we'll make
the right decision.
You're not alone,
Kathryn.
Hm.
Three years ago,
I didn't even know your name.
Today, I can't imagine
a day without you.
( com-link beeps )
TUVOK:
Captain Janeway to the Bridge.
JANEWAY:
Gentlemen?
Something strange
is going on.
The power signatures of those
Borg vessels have terminated.
All of them?
They're dead
in the water,
about 5.2 light-years
from here.
Cause.
Unknown.
Mr. Paris...
Captain?
Set a course
for their position, warp 2.
We're approaching
the ships.
Slow to impulse.
On screen.
( computers beeping )
( dramatic theme playing )
Life signs.
A few,
but they're erratic.
TUVOK:
Captain,
I'm detecting two residual
weapon signatures in the debris.
One is Borg.
The other is of unknown origin.
Who could do this to the Borg?
( dramatic theme continues )
Someone more powerful
than the Borg?
It's hard to imagine.
KIM:
But they did it--
Fifteen cubes.
We might have just
found our ticket
through Borg space--
An ally.
Let's not jump
to conclusions.
Scan the vicinity
for other vessels.
There are none.
Hold on.
I'm picking up some
sort of bio-readings.
They're coming
from the outer hull
of one of the Borg ships.
Let's see it.
Magnify, Mr. Kim.
KIM:
It's definitely organic,
but our sensors can't
penetrate its surface.
Send a standard
greeting.
No response.
This could be
a space-dwelling organism
or a biological weapon.
I'd like to know what kind of
weapon could destroy the Borg.
Can we beam it
away from the ship?
I can't get
a lock on it.
Tractor beam?
No effect.
KIM:
Whatever that thing is,
it's impervious
to our technology.
Tuvok...
are you reading an atmosphere
in the cube?
TUVOK:
Affirmative.
Commander Chakotay.
I want you to take
an away team inside.
Try to get a short-range scan
of the bio-mass.
There are still Borg life signs,
but they're unstable.
We'll keep an open com-link
and an active transporter lock,
and we'll pull you out of there
at the first sign of trouble.
Tuvok, Harry,
you're with me.
( door opens, closes )
( ominous theme playing )
This way.
( electrical static,
deep booming )
( instrument whirring )
TUVOK:
Lower your phasers.
If we don't appear threatening,
they should ignore us.
Looks like they're
a little preoccupied.
( loud, erratic whirring )
( beeping )
( electricity pops )
( beeping continues )
The alien bio-readings
are getting stronger.
We're close.
Commander?
TUVOK:
Curious.
That's not the word
I had in mind.
Those bodies
are reminiscent
of one of the premonitions
Kes described.
Didn't Kes say we were
all going to die?
Let's keep moving.
( ominous theme continues )
( air hissing )
( electricity pops )
( beeping continues )
CHAKOTAY:
It looks like the bio-mass
dissolved right
through the Borg hull.
TUVOK:
This Borg
is attempting
to assimilate it.
Doesn't look like
he's having much luck.
There's a chamber
beyond this opening,
40 meters wide,
high concentrations
of antimatter particles.
It looks like a warp propulsion
system of some kind.
It's a ship?
Starfleet has
encountered species
that use
organic-based vessels--
The Breen, for example.
There doesn't seem to be
anybody inside.
Chakotay to Voyager.
JANEWAY:
Go ahead, Commander.
Captain, we've found
an entrance to the bio-mass.
We think it might be
a ship of some kind.
Permission to go inside.
JANEWAY:
Granted.
Harry, that's a Borg
distribution node.
See if you can download
their tactical database.
It might contain a record
of what happened here.
Aye, sir.
CHAKOTAY: Tuvok.
( beeping )
( ominous theme continues )
CHAKOTAY:
They seem to be
organic conduits.
They're carrying
electrodynamic fluid.
TUVOK:
It may be an energy source.
Maybe.
This looks like
a binary matrix,
but it's laced
with neuropeptides.
Could be their version
of a computer core.
( beeping )
( clanging echoes )
( clanging )
This damage was caused
by a Borg disruptor beam.
The wall appears
to be regenerating itself.
Commander.
( clanging )
( clanging intensifies )
( screeching clang )
( screaming )
Kes?
Harry's in danger.
What do you see?
Get them out of there!
Sick Bay to Janeway.
KIM:
Commander!
There's something
in here with us
and it's not the Borg.
I can't localize it,
but it's within 20 meters.
Perhaps the pilot
has returned.
JANEWAY:
Voyager to away team.
Go ahead.
Stand by
for transport.
We're getting you out of there.
CHAKOTAY: Good idea.
Energize.
( beeping )
I can't get a lock on them.
What's the problem?
It looks like
bio-electric interference
from whatever's
coming toward them.
( beeping )
It's within seven meters.
Let's get out of here.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Narrow the confinement beam.
No effect.
I'm going to try
a skeletal lock.
A what?
I think I can get
a clean lock
on the minerals
in their bone tissue.
I just came up with it,
but I think it might work.
( suspenseful theme continues )
The life-form's five meters away
and closing.
From where?
( snarling )
( screaming )
I've got them.
A skeletal lock, huh?
We'll have to add that one
to the transporter manual.
( beeping )
Captain.
The bioship is powering up--
Like it's charging
some kind of weapon.
( groans )
Mr. Paris, get
us out of here--
Maximum warp.
( grunts )
The alien ship
is not pursuing.
JANEWAY:
Kes?
I could hear
its thoughts.
The pilot of the bioship
was trying
to communicate with me.
They're a telepathic species.
I've been aware of them
for some time now,
the premonitions.
Captain, it's not the Borg
that we should be
worried about. It's them.
What did it say to you?
It said...
"The weak...
will perish."
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 50984.3.
It's been 12 hours
since our confrontation
with the alien life-form.
There's no sign
that we're being pursued,
and we've had no further
encounters with the Borg.
I've decided
to hold our course.
The Northwest Passage
is only one day away,
and I won't allow fear
to undermine this crew's sense
of purpose...
even if that fear is justified.
The infection is
spreading.
What began with
a few stray cells
contaminating
the chest wound
is now infusing
every system in his body.
It looks like he's being
transformed in some way.
Not exactly.
The alien cells
are consuming his body
from the inside out.
In essence...
Mr. Kim is being
eaten alive.
He's still conscious,
Doctor?
I tried giving him
a sedative,
but it was rejected
immediately.
In fact, every treatment
I've tried
has been neutralized
within seconds.
( computer beeping )
These are alien cells.
Each one contains
more than a hundred times
the DNA of a human cell.
It's the most densely coded
life-form I've ever seen.
Even I would need years
to decipher it.
They have an extraordinary
immune response.
Anything that penetrates
the cell membrane...
chemical...biological...
technological...
it's all instantly
destroyed.
That's why the Borg
can't assimilate them.
Resistance in this case
is far from futile.
Nevertheless,
I believe Borg technology
holds the key
to saving Mr. Kim.
How so?
I hope to unleash
an army of modified
Borg nanoprobes
into his bloodstream,
designed to target
and eradicate the infection.
As you know, I've been
analyzing the nanoprobes.
They're efficient
little assimilators.
One can't help
but admire the workmanship.
But they're no match
for the alien cells.
So I successfully
dissected a nanoprobe
and managed to access
its recoding mechanism.
I reprogrammed the probe
to emit the same
electrochemical signatures
as the alien cells.
That way, the probe
can do its work
without being detected.
Observe.
The alien cells are completely
oblivious to the probe
until it's too late.
Unfortunately, I've only
created a few prototypes.
I'll need several days
to modify
enough nanoprobes
to cure Ensign Kim.
Does Harry have
several days?
I wish I knew.
( dramatic theme playing )
Fight it, Harry.
That's an order.
We've analyzed the Borg's
tactical database.
They refer to these new aliens
as "Species 8472."
Over the past five months,
the Borg have been
attacked by them
on at least
a dozen occasions.
Each time, the Borg
were defeated swiftly.
The Collective has very little
information about the species.
Is anything known about
where they come from?
I'm afraid so.
( console beeping )
Get the captain.
JANEWAY:
The Northwest Passage.
It's clear of Borg activity
for a very good reason.
I'm detecting 133 bioships.
More are approaching.
From where?
They seem to be coming
from a quantum singularity.
TORRES:
I'm localizing the
gravimetric distortions.
On screen.
Kes?
Anything?
Yes, I can hear them.
They're in a place
where they're all alone.
Nothing else lives there.
Some kind of
parallel universe?
I don't know.
I feel malevolence...
a cold hatred.
The weak will perish.
It's an invasion.
They intend on
destroying everything.
Tom, reverse course,
maximum warp.
Take us five light-years out
and hold position.
Aye, Captain.
Maintain Red Alert.
Commander?
That moment we spoke about?
It's here.
Any thoughts?
Just one.
Flying into that corridor
would mean certain death.
Agreed. The Northwest Passage
is no longer an option.
So now the choice is between
facing the Borg in their space
or finding a nice planet
here in the Delta Quadrant
and giving up
on ever getting home.
We'd be turning around,
but we wouldn't be giving up.
We may find
another way home.
I'm not ready to
walk onto that Bridge
and tell the crew
we're quitting.
I can't do it,
Chakotay, not yet.
There must be
another alternative.
Kathryn....
you haven't slept
in two days.
Try getting some rest
and clearing your head.
We're safe for the moment.
We can tell the crew tomorrow
if we have to.
See you in
the morning.
( door opens, closes )
( dramatic theme playing )
Maestro?
Leonardo.
Catarina...
buona sera.
Am I disturbing you?
What do you see?
A wall,
with candlelight
reflecting on it.
Why?
What do you see?
A flock of starlings...
the leaves on an oak...
a horse's tail...
a thief with a noose
around his neck...
Ah...
and a wall...
with the candlelight
reflecting on it.
There are times, Catarina,
when I find myself...
transfixed by a shadow
on the wall,
or the splashing of water
against a stone.
I stare at it,
the hours pass...
the world around me
drops away...
replaced by worlds
being created and destroyed
by my imagination...
a way to focus the mind.
Sit and tell me
why you have come.
There's a path before me...
the only way home.
And on either side,
mortal enemies
bent on destroying each other.
If I attempt to pass
through them,
I'll be destroyed as well.
But if I turn around,
that would end all hope
of ever getting home.
And no matter how much
I try to focus my mind,
I can't see an alternative.
When one's imagination
cannot provide an answer,
one must seek out
a greater imagination.
There are times
when even I find myself
kneeling in prayer.
I must deliver a bronzetto
to the monks at Santa Croce.
Come with me, Catarina, eh?
We will awake the abbot,
visit the chapel,
and appeal to God.
Somehow I don't think
that's going to work for me.
( suspenseful theme playing )
But there is an alternative
I hadn't considered.
What if I made an appeal...
...to the devil?
An alliance with the Borg?
More like...
an exchange.
We offer them a way
to defeat their new enemy,
and, in return,
we get safe passage
through their space.
In developing
a treatment for Harry,
the Doctor has found a way
to attack the aliens
at a microscopic level.
It's still in the experimental
stages, Captain.
I've only made
a few prototypes.
Nevertheless,
if we teach the Borg
how to modify
their own nanoprobes,
they'd have a blueprint
to create a weapon
to fight the aliens.
In theory, yes.
B'Elanna, it's clear
from the Borg database
that they know practically
nothing about Species 8472.
That's right. The Borg gain
knowledge through assimilation.
What they can't assimilate,
they can't understand.
But we don't assimilate.
We investigate, and in this
case, that's given us an edge.
We've discovered something
they need.
But the Borg aren't
exactly known
for their diplomacy.
How can we expect them
to cooperate with us?
Normally, the answer
would be no,
but if what I've learned
from the aliens is true,
the Borg are losing
this conflict.
In one regard,
the Borg are no different
than we are.
They're trying to survive.
I don't believe they're
going to refuse an offer
that will help them
do that.
What makes you think the Borg
won't attempt to
take the information
by assimilating Voyager
and its crew?
Because that won't
get them anywhere.
Doctor, you're
the only one on board
with full knowledge
of the nanoprobe modifications.
I want you to transfer
all of that research
into your holo-matrix.
Certainly.
You're my guarantee.
If the Borg threaten us
in any way,
we'll simply
erase your program.
But it won't
come to that, Doctor.
It's in the Collective's
own interest to cooperate.
Voyager is only one ship.
Our safe passage
is a small price to pay
for what we're offering
in exchange.
B'Elanna, assist the Doctor
with his transfer.
B'ELANNA: Aye, Captain.
Mr. Paris--
locate the nearest Borg vessel
and lay in a course.
They shouldn't
be difficult to find.
Yes, ma'am.
Dismissed.
You were awfully quiet.
I didn't want the
others to hear this,
but I think what you're
proposing is too great a risk.
How so?
There's a story I heard
as a child, a parable,
and I never forgot it.
A scorpion was walking along
the bank of a river
wondering how to get
to the other side.
Suddenly, he saw a fox.
He asked the fox to take him
on his back across the river.
The fox said, "No,
if I do that, you'll sting me,
and I'll drown."
The scorpion assured him,
"If I did that,
we'd both drown."
So the fox thought about it
and finally agreed.
So the scorpion
climbed up on his back,
and the fox began to swim.
But halfway across the river,
the scorpion stung him.
As the poison filled his veins,
the fox turned to the scorpion
and said, "Why did you do that?
Now, you'll drown too."
"I couldn't help it,"
said the scorpion.
"It's my nature."
I understand the risk...
...and I'm not proposing
that we try to change
the nature of the beast,
but this is a unique situation.
To our knowledge, the Borg
have never been so threatened.
They're vulnerable.
I think we can take
advantage of that.
Even if we do somehow
negotiate an exchange,
how long will they keep up
their end of the bargain?
It could take months
to get across Borg territory.
We'd be facing
thousands of systems,
millions of vessels.
But only one Collective, and
we've got them over a barrel.
We don't need to give them
a single bit of information,
not until we're safe.
We just need the courage
to see this through to the end.
There are other kinds
of courage,
like the courage to accept
that there are some situations
beyond your control.
Not every problem
has an immediate solution.
You're suggesting
we turn around.
Yes. We should
get out of harm's way.
Let them fight it out.
In the meantime, there's still
plenty of Delta Quadrant
left to explore.
We may find another way home.
Or we might find
something else.
Six months,
a year down the road.
After Species 8472
gets through with the Borg,
we could find ourselves
right back in the line of fire,
and we'll have missed
the window of opportunity
that exists right here,
right now.
How much is our safety worth?
What do you mean?
We'd be giving an advantage
to a race
guilty of murdering billions.
We'd be helping the Borg
assimilate yet another species,
just to get ourselves
back home-- It's wrong!
Tell that to Harry Kim.
He's barely alive,
thanks to that species.
Maybe helping to assimilate them
isn't such a bad idea.
We could be doing
the Delta Quadrant a favor.
I don't think
you really believe that.
I think you're struggling
to justify your plan
because your desire
to get this crew home
is blinding you
to other options.
I know you, Kathryn.
Sometimes...
...you don't know
when to step back.
Do you trust me, Chakotay?
That isn't the issue.
Oh, but it is.
Only yesterday, you were saying
that we'd face this together,
that you'd be at my side.
I still have to tell you
what I believe.
I'm no good to you
if I don't do that.
I appreciate your insights,
but the time for debate is over.
I've made my decision.
Now, do I have your support?
You're the Captain.
I'm the First Officer,
I'll follow your orders.
But that doesn't change
my belief
that we're making
a fatal mistake.
Then I guess I am alone
after all.
Dismissed.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
There are three planets
in this system.
Inhabitants, all Borg.
A vessel is approaching.
All stop.
Shields up.
They are hailing us.
Open a channel.
COLLECTIVE:
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
They've locked on to us
with a tractor beam.
Borg vessel.
This is Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
I have tactical information
about Species 8472.
I want to negotiate.
COLLECTIVE:
Negotiation is irrelevant.
You will be assimilated.
( console beeping )
JANEWAY:
Borg vessel, what you're
receiving is a sample of
the knowledge we possess.
If you don't disengage
your tractor beam immediately,
I will have
that data destroyed.
You have 10 seconds
to comply.
We know you're in danger
of being defeated.
You can't afford to risk
losing this information.
Disengage
your trac--
COLLECTIVE:
State your demands.
I want safe passage
through your space.
Once my ship
is beyond Borg territory,
I'll give you our research.
COLLECTIVE:
Unacceptable.
Our space is vast.
Your passage would require
too much time.
We need the technology now.
If I give it to you now,
you'll assimilate us.
COLLECTIVE:
Species 8472 must be stopped.
Our survival is your survival.
Give us the technology.
No.
Safe passage first
or no deal.
COLLECTIVE:
State your proposal.
Let's work together.
Combine our resources.
Even if we do give you
the technology now,
you're still going to need
time to develop it.
By working together,
we can create
a weapon more quickly.
If you escort us
through your space,
we can perfect
the weapon as we--
( rumbling )
( grunts )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Where did that ship come from?
A quantum singularity has
appeared 20,000 kilometers away.
The bioship is heading
directly toward the planet.
TORRES:
The Borg shields
are weakening.
We might be able to break free
of the tractor beam.
Can you get a lock
on the Captain?
Not yet.
Commander, there are
nine more bioships
coming out of
the singularity.
( groans )
What's going on?
( theme music playing )