Report.
The Borg shields
are off-line.
I've got a lock
on Captain Janeway.
Get her out of there and break
us free of the cube.
Stand by all weapons.
I'm trying to energize.
( console beeping denial )
The Borg are scattering
the beam.
Compensate.
No effect.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Commander,
cut the transporter beam.
Captain?
Do it.
I have reached an agreement
with the collective.
We're going to help them design
a weapon against Species 8472.
In exchange, they've granted us
safe passage
through their space.
Cube is altering course.
They're heading toward
the Alpha Quadrant.
That's part of the plan.
We'll work on the weapon
en route.
Once we're across
their territory,
we'll give them the nanoprobes.
They appear to be holding up
their end of the bargain.
I suggest we do the same.
How do you propose
we begin this "collaboration"?
I'm going to work here
on the cube.
They have technology
that'll make the job go faster.
I want to take advantage of it.
It's not necessary
for you to stay there.
We can set up a com-link
with the Borg...
It's part of the deal.
I work here.
All right.
As long as we're cooperating...
maybe the Borg would be willing
to disengage their tractor beam.
We can match their course
without a leash.
I'll propose it.
Mr. Tuvok, transport
to my coordinates.
Understood.
We're going to make this work,
Commander. Janeway out.
You heard the Captain.
DOCTOR:
I've replicated nearly ten
million Borg nanoprobes,
each of them reprogrammed
to my specifications,
each capable
of targeting the alien tissue.
Assimilating it?
Just momentarily.
The Borg technology will
denaturate within seconds
taking the alien tissue
along with it.
Mr. Kim, I'm about to
inject your carotid artery.
You'll feel a
tingling sensation.
Don't be alarmed.
Nice to see you
again, Ensign.
It's working.
Prepare another dose
of nanoprobes.
Yes, Doctor.
Good work.
Let me know when he's
back on his feet.
Commander,
I must tell you,
I have my doubts
about this alliance.
You may have
convinced the Borg
the nanoprobes can
defeat their enemy,
but a medical treatment is
a long way from a weapon of war.
We'll leave that
to the Captain.
This situation
is unpredictable,
so we're going to stay
at full Red Alert.
Keep all information
about the nanoprobes
stored in your holo-matrix.
Don't worry.
I'll delete myself
at the first
sign of trouble.
Well... maybe not
the first sign.
TORRES:
We've just received word.
Tuvok beamed to the cube.
He's joined the Captain.
Keep a transporter lock
on both of them.
I'll try, but the Borg are
regenerating their shields.
Try matching
their shield frequencies.
It won't work. They'll be able
to adapt too quickly.
I don't want to hear
what we can't do!
Just find a way
to get our people
out of there if we have to.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
They've released
their tractor beam.
Match their
course and speed.
I never thought I'd hear
myself say this, but...
looks like the Borg
are cooperating.
( snarling )
( screaming )
DOCTOR:
Kes, Kes!
Kes! What's wrong?
They're watching us.
TUVOK:
May I ask where
we're being taken?
Grid nine-two
of subjunction 12--
our very own workspace. It's
near the center of the cube.
These are my tricorder readings
of the bioship we examined.
I believe you will find
them most revealing.
Have you compared this
to the Doctor's analysis
of the alien tissue?
Yes. Many of the cellular
structures are identical.
The aliens and their ships
are made of the same
organic material.
Apparently so.
COLLECTIVE:
You have entered grid nine-two
of subjunction 12.
Proceed.
All right.
We've analyzed one
of the alien vessels
and it appears to be constructed
of organic material
vulnerable
to the modified nanoprobes.
I suggest we begin thinking
about a large-scale
delivery system.
A way to infect their ships
and destroy them
at the microsc-- Ugh!
We will begin.
What are you doing?
A neuro-transceiver is required
for maximum communication.
We will work as one mind.
No, that wasn't the agreement.
The neural link is temporary.
You will not be damaged.
I don't care.
I prefer to communicate
verbally, thank you.
Your primitive communication
is inefficient.
On the contrary...
we work better
with our individuality intact.
Surely, we've proven that
to you by now.
Irrelevant.
You must comply.
We "must" do nothing.
Tell your drone
to remove the transceiver.
What about choosing
a representative,
a single Borg we can work with
and talk to directly?
Elaborate.
You've done it before
when you transformed
Jean-Luc Picard into Locutus.
We will not be assimilated.
Choose a representative,
or the deal's off!
( grunts )
( door clangs open )
I speak for the Borg.
I'm Captain Janeway. This is
Lieutenant Tuvok.
We are aware
of your designations.
What's your designation?
Seven of Nine,
Tertiary Adjunct of
Unimatrix Zero One.
But you may call me
Seven of Nine.
You are proposing
a large-scale weapon.
We concur.
I thought you might.
We could encase the nanoprobes
in some of our photon torpedoes,
in essence, turn them
into biomolecular warheads.
Your torpedoes
are inadequate.
They lack the necessary range
and dispersive force.
Do you have
a better idea?
We are Borg.
I take that as a "yes."
A multikinetic
neutronic mine,
five million isoton yield.
An explosion that size
could affect an
entire star system.
Correct.
The shock wave will disperse
the nanoprobes over a radius
of five light-years.
JANEWAY:
That's somewhat larger
than I had in mind.
You're proposing a weapon
of mass destruction.
We are.
Well, I'm not.
You'd be endangering
innocent worlds.
It would be efficient.
We would need approximately
50 trillion nanoprobes
to arm this mine.
It would take the Doctor
several weeks
to replicate that amount.
You are losing
this conflict.
Are you willing
to risk further delay?
JANEWAY:
Right now,
your enemy believes
it is invulnerable.
If we create smaller weapons
using our torpedoes,
and destroy
a few of their bioships
it may deter them,
convince them
to give up this war.
You are individuals.
You are small
and you think
in small terms.
But the present
situation requires
that we consider your plan.
Voyager's
weapons inventory.
Photon torpedo complement, 32,
class-6 warhead.
Explosive yield,
200 isotons.
How did you obtain
this information?
We are Borg.
Naturally.
Commander, we have
some disturbing news.
At this point,
I'm getting used to it.
Her telepathic visions
are increasing,
both in frequency and intensity.
It feels different
this time.
It's almost like...
they're right here
in the room.
DOCTOR:
There it is again.
I'm trying
to block them out...
but I can't.
Every time she has a vision,
specific regions
of her cerebral cortex go into
a state of hyper-stimulation--
memory engrams,
perceptual centers.
I can't be sure, but I think
there's more going on here
than just a simple "hello."
Enhance this grid.
I want to take a closer look
at the detonator.
We must analyze the bioship.
Your data.
You're human, aren't you?
This body was assimilated
18 years ago.
It ceased to be
human at that time.
I'm curious.
What was your name before--?
Do not engage us
in further irrelevant discourse.
( buzzing beeps )
We are being hailed
by your vessel.
Commander, what is it?
It's Kes.
The Doctor believes
that the aliens
are accessing her memory.
If that's true, they may already
know what we're planning.
I've ordered long-range scans
for bioships. Nothing so far.
We should alter course,
try to throw them off.
Agreed.
Our course and heading
have been changed.
Match them and keep me apprised
of any changes
in Kes.
Chakotay out.
We now require
one of your photon torpedoes
and the nanoprobes.
One step at a time.
We're not safely across
your territory yet.
We must construct
and test a prototype now.
The risk of attack
has increased.
Irrelevant. We have an
agreement.
You're asking me
to give up my only guarantee
that you won't assimilate us.
I won't risk it.
Are you willing to risk
a direct confrontation with us?
If we transport
500 drones onto your vessel,
do you believe you could offer
sufficient resistance?
We'd die trying.
That won't be necessary.
We must construct
a launching system
to accommodate this design.
CHAKOTAY:
Glad you could join us, Mr. Kim.
PARIS:
Harry, welcome back.
Thanks. Reporting
for duty, sir.
The Doctor gave me
a clean bill of health.
Did I miss anything?
Not too much.
Take your station, Ensign.
You've still got a tendril
up your nose.
PARIS:
Commander,
I'm picking up
gravimetric distortions.
12,000 kilometers aft.
It's a singularity.
( alarm sounds softly )
We are under attack.
They're charging weapons.
Shields.
Keep a lock
on the away team.
Direct hit
to our secondary hull.
( console beeping )
Transporters are off-line.
Shields and weapons are down.
Voyager has taken heavy damage.
We cannot let the
nanoprobes be destroyed.
We're being targeted.
Brace for impact.
The cube?
Destroyed... and it took
the bioship with it.
( haltingly ):
Tuvok to Chakotay.
Go ahead, Tuvok.
Where are you?
I'm in Cargo Bay 2...
( grunting )
along with the Captain...
and a number of Borg.
We were beamed over
just before impact.
We require assistance.
Tuvok? Tuvok?
Secure that deck.
Security team
to Cargo Bay 2.
Paris, you have the Bridge.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Lower your weapons.
We are here
with your Captain's consent.
It was necessary
to sacrifice our vessel
to protect yours.
We have an alliance,
do we not?
CHAKOTAY:
For now, they're contained.
They've assimilated Cargo Bay 2
and are drawing energy
from the secondary
power couplings.
But they've gone
no further?
Not yet.
I've sealed off Decks 9
through 13 and posted security
details at every access point.
I suggest we
increase security
around Sick Bay as well.
Already done.
How far did you get
on the weapon?
We are ready to
construct a prototype.
You're fit to return
back to duty, Lieutenant.
And you, Kes?
Oh, I'm all right.
The visions have
stopped for now.
The plasma burns to her
thoracic region I can treat
and I've already stopped
the internal bleeding,
but her neural injuries
are going to require some...
creative thinking.
Before we beamed out,
an alien energy discharge
struck very near the Captain.
Well, it appears to have
disrupted
all her neuroelectrical
pathways.
I'll have to induce a coma
to protect
her higher brain functions,
but I must tell you,
unless I can
repair the damage...
she may never
regain consciousness.
Make sure those Borg stay put.
I want tactical updates
every 20 minutes.
Aye, sir. Shall I resume
working with them?
Stand by for now.
The Captain wishes
to speak with you.
Please keep it brief.
( weakly ):
The Doctor...
explained my condition.
You are in command.
I understand.
They'll push you...
they'll threaten you,
but they need you.
They need this alliance.
You have to make this work.
I want you to
make this work.
Get this crew home.
I must begin.
Where is
your Captain?
I must speak with her.
In our medical bay,
recovering.
You'll be dealing
with me now.
Circumstances have changed.
I'd say so.
The loss of our vessel requires
that we modify our agreement.
I've been giving that
some thought.
I'm willing
to let you stay on board.
We'll continue to work
with you on the weapon.
Once we're safely out
of Borg territory,
we'll give you
the nanoprobes,
shake hands
and part company.
Insufficient.
Our latest tactical
projections indicate
that the war
will be lost by then.
The nearest Borg vessel
is 40 light-years away.
You will reverse course
and take us to it.
Even at maximum warp,
that's a five-day journey,
in the wrong direction.
We're supposed to be
heading out of Borg space
not deeper into it.
There is no alternative.
Look...
I'll honor
the original agreement,
but I'm not turning
this ship around.
It's too dangerous.
Denying our request
is also dangerous.
I'll think about it.
Think quickly.
A five-day trip back into
the heart of Borg territory,
it's too risky.
With those drones
and the nanoprobes on board,
we might as well have a
bull's-eye painted on our hull.
We're a prime target
for Species 8472.
We'd never survive
another attack.
What is the
alternative?
I'm going to end this alliance,
here and now.
We're going to
drop the Borg off
on the next
uninhabited planet,
give them the nanoprobes
and take our chances alone.
They can wait for a Borg ship
to pick them up
and finish the weapon.
I'm in command now
and I have to do what I think
is best for this crew.
Tom, I want you to scan
for the nearest uninhabited
planet and set a course.
Aye, sir.
I must caution you, Commander.
The Borg may not
go quietly.
We'll see.
Bring that female drone
to the ready room.
Dismissed.
Once we've beamed
you to the surface,
we'll send down
the nanoprobes
and all our research.
Unacceptable.
We don't have time...
This isn't open
for discussion.
I'm not turning
this ship around.
You're getting what you wanted.
I suggest
we part ways amicably.
There is another option.
We could assimilate your vessel.
If a single drone
steps one millimeter
out of that cargo bay,
I'll decompress the entire deck.
You won't pose much of a threat
floating in space.
When your Captain
first approached us,
we suspected that an agreement
with humans would prove
impossible to maintain.
You are erratic,
conflicted,
disorganized.
Every decision is debated,
every action questioned,
every individual entitled
to their own small opinion.
You lack harmony, cohesion...
greatness.
It will be your undoing.
Escort our guest back
to the cargo bay.
Well, I've made my decision.
If it were only a matter
of going against the orders
of my superior officer...
You're more
than just my Captain.
You're my friend.
I hope you'll understand.
COLLECTIVE:
Species 8472 has penetrated
matrix 010,
grid 19.
Eight planets destroyed.
312 vessels disabled.
4,000,621 Borg eliminated.
We must seize control
of the Alpha Quadrant vessel
and take it
into the alien realm.
We understand.
Class-H moon,
oxygen-argon atmosphere.
It'll do. Take us out of warp,
and enter orbit.
Aye, sir.
Tuvok...
stand by to transport the Borg
directly from the cargo bay.
After they're on the surface,
have security run a sweep of--
I'm reading power fluctuations
in the deflector array.
Cause?
It looks like the Borg
have accessed
deflector control.
They're trying to realign
the emitters.
Shut them out.
They've bypassed
security protocols.
They're emitting
a resonant graviton beam.
It's creating another
singularity!
Reverse course.
We're fighting intense
gravimetric distortion.
I can't break free!
Bridge to Cargo Bay 2.
Stop what you're doing,
or I'll depressurize that deck
and blow you out into space.
This is your final warning.
Do it.
Decompression cycle complete.
I still don't have
deflector control.
Commander,
a single Borg has survived.
We're being pulled in!
Report.
TUVOK:
We appear to have crossed
an interdimensional rift.
( console beeping )
We've definitely
left our galaxy.
No stars, no planets.
Let's see.
TORRES:
I'm recalibrating sensors.
The entire region
is filled with...
with some kind of organic fluid.
This isn't space.
It's matter.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Commander Chakotay.
We have entered the domain
of Species 8472.
Report to the cargo bay.
Paris, repressurize
Cargo Bay 2.
Tuvok.
Our entry into
fluidic space
has created a
compression wave.
They know we're here.
A fleet of bioships is already
converging on our position.
Time to intercept:
three hours, 17 minutes.
You've been here before.
How else could you know
about fluidic space?
We must prepare this vessel
for the altercation.
We will construct a complement
of biomolecular war--
Why?
Why were you here?
You started this war...
didn't you?
What's the matter?
Our galaxy wasn't
big enough for you?
You had to conquer
new territory?
But this race fought back--
A species as malevolent
as your own.
Species 8472 was more resistant
than we anticipated.
Their technology
is biogenically engineered.
It is superior to that
of all other species
we have previously
encountered.
Which is precisely
what you wanted.
They are the apex
of biological evolution.
Their assimilation
would have greatly added
to our own perfection.
So, instead of assimilating
these aliens,
you opened a door for them
to our galaxy.
There is only one
course of action.
Destroy them first.
My subspace link
to the collective
has been weakened
by the interdimensional rift.
We cannot signal for help.
We are alone.
We must construct a complement
of biomolecular warheads
and modify your weapons
to launch them.
I've got a better idea.
Why don't you open up
that rift again
and take us back?
If I do that, you will
no longer cooperate.
Doctor to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
Report to Sick Bay at once.
On my way.
Captain?
Ah, as you can see,
I've repaired
her neural damage.
Ensign Kim, the Captain.
I'm two for two.
Doctor, if you'll excuse us
for a moment.
Hmm?
Eh?
Oh. Gladly.
Computer, deactivate
EMH program.
The Doctor brought
me up to speed,
but he couldn't tell me
what I really wanted to know.
Why?
The collective ordered me
to reverse course,
travel 40 light-years
back the way we came.
What would you have done?
I probably would have
reversed course--
maintained the alliance
as long as possible.
In my mind, the alliance
was already over.
You never trusted me. You never
believed this would work.
You were just waiting
for an opportunity
to circumvent my orders.
Trust had nothing to do with it.
I made a tactical decision.
And so did I.
They've been taking advantage
of us from day one.
We made concessions,
so did they.
They lied.
The Borg started the war
with Species 8472.
We've only got one Borg left
to worry about.
We should try
to disable her
and get back
to the Delta Quadrant.
We might be able to duplicate
the deflector protocols
they used to open a singularity.
No.
I won't be caught tinkering
with the deflector
when those aliens attack.
There is no other way out
of this, Chakotay.
It's too late for opinions. It's
too late for discussion.
It's time to make the call,
and I'm making it.
We fight the aliens, in full
cooperation with the Borg.
I was linked
to a collective once, remember?
I had a neuro-transceiver
embedded in my spine.
I know who we're dealing with.
We've got to get rid
of that last Borg
and take our chances alone.
It won't work.
This isn't working, either.
There are two wars going on,
the one out there
and the one in here, and...
we're losing both of them.
"It will be your undoing."
What?
Our conflicted nature,
our individuality.
Seven of Nine said
that we lacked
the cohesion
of a collective mind.
That one day,
it would divide us
and destroy us.
And here we are,
proving her point.
I'll tell you when we lost
control of this situation,
when we made our mistake.
It was the moment
we turned away from each other.
We don't have to stop being
individuals to get through this.
We just have to stop
fighting each other.
Captain Janeway.
I've relieved Mr. Chakotay
of his duties
and confined him to the brig.
I'm back in command.
And you understand
the situation?
Completely.
Tuvok, give her the nanoprobes.
Work with her.
Build as many warheads
as you can
and start modifying
our weapon systems.
I suggest we think about
enhancing our defenses as well.
If we're going
to fight this battle,
I intend to win it.
We are in agreement.
Good.
This is the plan.
We engage the enemy here,
in their space.
We show them
what they're up against.
If they have any sense
of self-preservation,
they'll back off,
pull their ships out
of the Delta Quadrant.
That's provided
the weapons are effective.
If they aren't...
it's been nice
working with you.
We've got to get this
ship armed and ready
in under two hours.
We're going to war.
Borg modifications are complete.
Bring them on line.
Torpedo launch tubes active.
Hull armor
engaged.
Shield enhancements stable.
Biomolecular weapons are ready.
13 standard photon torpedoes
and one class-10 armed
with a high-yield
warhead.
All hands,
this is the Captain.
Ready your stations,
seal all emergency
bulkheads, and prepare
to engage the enemy.
Stand by for my orders.
Four bioships
have just entered sensor range.
Battle stations.
( alarm sounding )
I've got a visual.
On screen.
I can hear them.
They want to talk through me.
They say we've contaminated
their realm.
Tell them we had no choice.
We were only trying
to defend ourselves.
They say our galaxy is impure.
Its proximity is a threat
to their... genetic integrity.
Tell them we have a weapon,
a devastating weapon
that can destroy them
at the cellular level.
If they don't stop their attacks
on the Delta Quadrant,
we'll be forced to use it.
They said, "Your galaxy
will be purged."
( groaning )
( grunts )
Shields and weapons
are off-line!
Rerouting emergency power
to the launchers.
They're coming around
for another assault!
I've lost thrusters!
Biomolecular warheads
are charged and ready.
Fire.
Direct hit on all four vessels.
No effect.
They're charging weapons.
The nanoprobes were successful,
if not prompt.
All four ships
have been destroyed.
I think we've made our point.
Now open a singularity
and get us out of here.
Captain.
Kes, are you still in contact?
Yes.
Tell them if they continue
their attack,
we'll use the weapon again.
They're not responding.
Evasive maneuvers.
PARIS: Aye, Captain.
They're in pursuit.
Prepare to fire
the high-yield warhead.
Aft torpedo bay.
Ready, Captain.
Do it.
Thirteen bioships
have been destroyed.
The others
are in retreat.
I have regained full contact
with the collective.
What are they saying?
All remaining bioships
in the Delta Quadrant
are returning to their realm.
The Borg have prevailed.
With a little help from us.
Now, it's time you fulfilled
your end of the agreement.
Tell the collective
we expect safe passage
from here on out. We'll give you
a shuttlecraft.
You can head
for the nearest Borg ship.
Unacceptable.
This alliance is terminated.
Your ship and its crew
will adapt
to service us.
Resistance is futile.
Captain, she's tapping
into helm control.
She's trying to access
our coordinates.
Shut her out.
I can't.
Bridge to Chakotay. Scorpion.
CHAKOTAY:
Seven of Nine,
stop what you're doing.
You're human,
a human individual.
Our minds are linked.
We are one.
I can hear your thoughts.
His link is stable,
but it won't be for long.
You must hurry.
Just a few more seconds.
I can see your memories.
You remember being human.
We are Borg.
I see a young girl.
A family.
Irrelevant.
Your appeal to my humanity
is pointless.
Almost there, Chakotay. You've
got to keep her distracted
if we're going
to make this work.
Listen to your human side...
to yourself...
the little girl.
( beeping warning )
Seven of Nine... Annika.
He's losing the link!
Initiating power surge...
now!
( gasps )
( cries out )
( yelling )
( groaning )
Her connection
to the collective is severed.
Get her to Sick Bay.
Bridge to Doctor.
Report.
Commander Chakotay's going
to be all right,
although he may wake up
with a bit of a headache.
Tom, plot a course
out of Borg space,
maximum warp.
Yes, ma'am.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51003.7.
Three days, and no sign
of Borg or bioships.
We appear to be out of danger,
but the entire crew is on edge
and so am I.
Not even the calm
of Master da Vinci's workshop
is enough to ease my mind.
( holodeck door opens )
Am I interrupting?
Not at all.
I'm just finishing up my log.
The old-fashioned way.
I wanted to get as far away
from bio-implants
and fluidic space and...
and this feels
more human somehow.
I hate to spoil the mood, but
you might want to take a look
at this Engineering report.
It'll take at least two weeks
to remove the Borg technology
from our systems.
B'Elanna did note
that the power couplings
on Deck 8 work better
with the Borg
improvements.
Leave them.
How is our passenger?
The Doctor says
she's stabilizing.
Her human cells
are starting to regenerate.
I wonder what's left under
all that Borg technology...
if she can ever
become human again.
You plan to keep her on board?
We pulled the plug.
We're responsible
for what happens to her now.
She was assimilated
at a very young age.
The collective's
all she knows.
She might not
want to stay.
I think she might.
We have something
the Borg could never offer.
Friendship.
I want you to know
that disobeying your orders
was one of the most difficult
things I've ever had to do.
I understand.
And I respect
the decision you made,
even though I disagree with it.
What's important
is that, in the end,
we got through this, together.
I don't ever want that
to change.
Agreed.
Good. Well...
I think it's time
we get back to our Bridge.
No argument there.