( energy crackling )
Commander Chakotay.
I understand you wanted
to see me.
I'm told you are the officer
in charge of personnel
that you prepare
the duty assignments.
Is that the correct phrase?
That's right.
I'm finding it... difficult
to spend so much time alone.
I am unaccustomed to it.
The hours do not pass quickly.
I can understand that.
How can we help?
I've been considering
the matter carefully.
I would like to request
a duty assignment.
Did you have something
specific in mind?
Yes.
Now what?
There's been a rupture
in the coolant injector.
I can see that.
Why haven't you sealed it off?
I'm attempting to do so.
That's better.
Lieutenant, I have an idea.
Perhaps it would be advisable
to reconfigure
the coolant assembly.
That would give us
greater control
over the pressure
valve emissions.
You are probably right.
And tomorrow we can do it
first thing, but not today.
I don't understand. Why wait
until tomorrow when today...?
TORRES:
Not today, Vorik.
PARIS:
Good morning.
Here's the helm control
evaluation you wanted.
Thank you.
We still on for dinner tonight?
I may have to work.
I'll let you know.
Aha. Okay.
Have you decided if you're...
if you're going through with it?
I have, and I'm not.
Today hasn't started out
very well
and the last thing I need
is to get involved with
some obscure Klingon ritual.
You were the one
who suggested it.
I know. And for one
sentimental minute
I thought that I might
actually go through with it
but not anymore.
Of course not.
Wouldn't want to get
too sentimental.
I overslept this morning
because I forgot to tell
the computer to wake me
and then the acoustic inverter
in my sonic shower blew out.
That'll make your hair
stand on end.
So I didn't have
time for breakfast.
And when I got here,
two people were out sick
so I had to cancel
the fuel cell overhaul.
And then an injector
burst for no apparent reason
and started spewing
plasma coolant.
That's a run of
bad luck, alright.
So, I'm in a bad mood,
and I know that I'm being
a little bit testy.
No. That's okay.
Think about that dinner.
Be careful.
Something interesting
just happened.
What's that?
Seven of Nine requested
a duty assignment.
Fascinating.
She wants to work
in Engineering.
What?
The Borg use
transwarp conduits
to travel through space
faster than warp speed.
If we could create
one of them...
we don't know anything
about transwarp technology.
Playing around with it
could be dangerous.
That's where
Seven of Nine comes in.
She's offered
to work with you.
What do you think
her real motives are?
She's having a tough time
making the transition
from the collective.
She wants something to do.
I never thought of you
as naive, Chakotay.
Bottom line is,
I don't want her working
in Engineering.
The bottom line is,
I'm giving you an order
and you're going to
follow it, Lieutenant.
Whatever you say, sir.
( exasperated sigh )
JANEWAY:
Seven of Nine,
you told me you wouldn't
make any more attempts
to contact the Borg.
I want to believe
that's true.
I assure you it is.
I've decided
not to post
a security detail while
you're in Engineering
but you have to realize
there are rules.
You'll be expected
to follow our protocols.
You'll report directly
to Lieutenant Torres
and obey any order
she gives you.
I understand.
One more thing--
your designation,
"Seven of Nine"
is a little cumbersome.
Wouldn't you prefer
to be called
by your given name, Annika?
I have been Seven of Nine
for as long as I can remember.
All right.
But maybe we could
streamline it a little.
How would you feel about...
"Seven"?
Imprecise...
but acceptable.
Tuvok to Captain Janeway.
Yes, Tuvok?
Please come to the Bridge.
A ship is approaching.
It's damaged,
but functional.
Energy emissions
are so low
it's probably not
capable of warp speed.
Several dozen
life signs aboard.
We are being
hailed, captain.
Open a channel.
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
starship Voyager.
I am Rahmin.
My people are the Caatati.
I apologize
for our appearance
and the condition of our ship.
Most of our people
were assimilated by the Borg
over a year ago.
We lost everything.
How many of you escaped?
A few thousand, on 30 ships--
all that's left
from a planet of millions.
I'm sorry.
Captain,
I want to assure you
my people were once
proud and accomplished.
I understand.
It pains me
to have to ask this
but I have 88 people
to care for on this vessel.
Is there any way
you could help us?
Of course.
Send us a list of your needs
and we'll see what we can do.
I'm deeply grateful.
If it's not too much to ask
is there any way
you might also spare
a small quantity
of thorium isotopes?
Without them,
our systems can't function.
I think we can arrange that.
I'll speak to my engineer.
You can't imagine
what this means to us,
Captain.
Thank you.
How are those thorium isotopes
coming, Vorik?
I'll admit I'm
having trouble
controlling the
neutron absorption.
Try increasing
the temperature of the plasma.
Get the thorium to the captain
as soon as it's ready.
Of course.
Tell me something...
when you hear about people
like the Caatati
do you have any feelings
of remorse?
No.
That's it?
Just "no"?
What further answer
do you require?
Oh, maybe some kind
of acknowledgment
of the billions of lives
you helped destroy.
A justification
for what you did.
Maybe... a little
sense of guilt.
Guilt is irrelevant.
Heartwarming.
I've set the parameters
for the tachyon burst
we'll need to create
a transwarp conduit.
It will be several hours
before the main deflector
can be modified.
I think it would be best
if I waited in my alcove.
I think you're right.
( sighing )
If I ever saw a job
for the morale officer,
it's sitting right here.
I'll bet I can help.
You're facing
a big challenge, Neelix.
I enjoy a challenge.
Is that supposed
to make me feel better?
Blood pie,
for the day of honor.
How did you know about that?
Has Tom been talking to you?
Not at all.
No, I-I make it a point
to know these things.
And if I'm correct,
many Klingon families
traditionally serve
blood pie on the day of honor.
I appreciate
the gesture, Neelix,
but I've decided to ignore
this particular tradition.
No blood pie, no examining
my behavior over the last year
to see if I measure up
to Klingon standards.
Understood.
Lieutenant...
without knowing why
there's a black cloud
hanging over your head,
may I suggest something?
Go right ahead.
You have a...
bit of a temper...
that you keep reined in,
and sometimes,
it builds up inside you
until you explode
at someone.
I'd say that about sums it up.
I'm offering to be
a pressure valve.
A what?
You may use me
to blow off steam.
When you're angry,
come see me.
Call me names, insult me,
question my parentage.
I won't take it personally
and you won't need
to keep things
bottled up inside anymore.
That may be the nicest offer
I've had in a long time.
Thank you, Neelix.
You're sweet, but I'm not sure
I could do that to you.
I'm here if you need me.
Neelix...
about this day of honor.
Do you think
I should go through with it?
I've always thought traditions
were good things...
worth preserving.
I've been thinking
a lot about...
the rituals
that my mother taught me, and...
they don't seem quite so hateful
as they did when I was a child.
Maybe being so far away from
anything Klingon has changed me.
It certainly can't hurt
to go through
with the ceremony.
I don't know
what effect it'll have on me.
That's what's frightening.
( sighing )
All right.
Bring on the blood pie.
( sighing )
I can do this.
Qu'pla!
What warrior goes there?
My name's B'elanna.
Have you come
to have your honor challenged?
I guess so. Yes.
Are you willing to see
the ceremony through to the end?
That's the idea, isn't it?
What do I do?
It will be a lengthy ordeal.
First, you must eat
from the heart
of a sanctified targ.
Pak lohr!
Yes... the heart of a targ
brings courage
to one who eats it.
Next you will drink mot'loch
from the Grail of Kahless.
Drink to the
glory of Kahless,
the greatest warrior
of all time.
( choking )
Kahless defeated his enemies
on the field of battle,
and built a mighty empire.
How have you proven
yourself worthy?
Um, I haven't built any empires,
and I can't say
that I've personally defeated
any enemies in battle
but you have to realize,
I'm not living among warriors.
Then how do you expect
to distinguish yourself?
I don't know. I guess
I'm doing the best I can.
Huh! A pitiful reply.
Let us proceed.
A warrior must endure
great hardship.
To test your mettle
you will endure the
ritual of 20 painsticks.
After that, you will
engage in combat
with a master
of the bat'leth.
Finally, you will traverse
the sulfur lagoons of Gorath.
You know, I don't think so.
I didn't want to do this
before you described it.
Certainly not now.
I'm leaving.
Not until you have
completed the ceremony, p'tahk.
( yells in pain )
( gasping )
( grunting and groaning )
( panting )
Thanks so much.
It's been lovely.
( door beeping )
Come in.
I tried to find you before,
but you were on the holodeck.
That's right.
You know, you left it running.
There was a Klingon in there
who didn't look too happy.
Really.
Yeah, and he was nursing
a whale of a black eye.
Looks like he had a run-in
with someone having
a really bad day.
That's very funny.
So, how'd it go?
It didn't.
Do you mind if we
talk about something else?
As a matter of fact, I do.
You have been like
a spitting cobra all day
and it's getting boring.
You know, we designed that
holodeck program together,
and I think you owe me
the courtesy of telling me
what happened.
It was ridiculous,
meaningless posturing.
Honor, dishonor--
what does it matter?
It matters because
it's part of who you are.
You've been running away
from that your whole life.
Who are you to
tell me that?
I care about you.
But if you're going
to keep pushing me away
then there's no point
in my staying around, is there?
Fine.
Just leave me alone.
Oh, don't worry. If this
is the way you treat people
who try to be your friend,
you'll be alone, all right.
There are over 200 people
on our three ships alone.
Every one of them
suffers from malnourishment
but it's been hardest
on the children.
Every parent
sacrifices for their child
but even so,
there's not enough food.
If you could hear
the crying of the babies
you would have as much trouble
sleeping at night as I do.
Have you considered relocation
to a planet where you
could grow your own food?
Of course...
but we haven't
been welcomed anywhere.
Because we have
no resources,
everyone treats us
like vagrants,
even criminals.
We're not
unsympathetic
but we have
limited supplies.
We can't possibly provide
enough for all your people
Forgive me,
but from my perspective,
you live in luxury.
You don't suffer from
debilitating diseases.
You have many sources
of energy-- replicators.
Your crew is very well fed.
Apparently,
keeping your bellies full
is more important to you
than helping those
less fortunate.
NEELIX:
That's unfair.
These are the most generous
people you could hope to meet.
But if we gave supplies
to everyone who asked
we wouldn't have anything left.
Neelix, how much food
can we spare?
We could provide each ship
with several hundred kilograms.
Do it. And check with
the doctor
to see if he can spare
any medical supplies.
Aye, Captain.
LUMAS:
Thank you.
May the gods smile
on you and your crew.
Tuvok, please escort
our guest
to the transporter room.
I've never navigated
a transwarp conduit.
Any problems I
should be aware of?
You'll have no idea
what you're doing.
If we attempt
to enter one,
I'll have to take
helm control.
I am a quick study.
What species is that?
A human who lived as a Borg.
Borg!
She is disconnected
from the collective.
She won't harm you.
Where's my wife?!
Where are my children?!
What did you do with them
after you took them?!
What did you do
with my family?!
Mr. Paris,
please proceed.
I lost everything--
my family, my home...!
Sorry about that.
About what?
Well, the way
he reacted to you.
He didn't injure me.
Good.
There are many
people on this ship
who have similar
feelings toward me.
I'm afraid you're right.
Does that bother you?
No.
Well, I'm not
one of those people.
We all have a past.
What matters is now.
I'm uncertain what
you're trying to say.
That...
if there's any way
that I can help you
adjust to your life
here on Voyager,
please ask me.
I will remember your offer.
( footsteps approaching )
All systems are ready.
We're only going
to take a peek.
We open a conduit, get as
much sensor data as we can
and then close it up.
I want to take this
one step at a time.
VORIK:
I've set up a temporary
tachyon matrix
within the main deflector.
It's on line.
Engineering to the Bridge.
We're ready to start, Captain.
Go ahead. We'll monitor
your progress from here.
We'll need to be at warp speed
to create a large enough
subspace field.
I'd like to re-route
helm control to Engineering.
Agreed. Janeway out.
Take us past...
Past warp two. I know.
We're at warp 2.3.
All right.
Vorik, start emitting
the tachyons.
Energizing the matrix.
There's no indication
of a subspace field.
I'd recommend switching
to a higher energy band.
( electronic humming )
That did something.
The subspace
field is forming.
Tachyon particles are leaking
into the propulsion system!
Shut down the deflector.
Done, but the leak
is continuing.
Janeway to Engineering.
Tachyons are flooding
the warp core, captain!
If you can't stabilize
the core immediately,
evacuate Engineering.
Aye, Captain.
I'll get back to you.
I've cut all power relays,
but the tachyon levels
are still rising.
All right. Everybody out!
Now!
That means you as well.
I could be of help.
That's an order!
You can't order me.
I outrank you.
We've got to neutralize
the core.
I'll try decoupling
the dilithium matrix.
No effect!
Try it again.
It's not working!
The core's
about to breach!
I've got to try
one more thing.
B'elanna,
there's no time!
We've got to
get out of here!
Come on.
Computer, prepare
to eject the warp core
Authorization:
Torres Omega 5-9-3.
Computer, eject
the warp core.
Torres to Janeway.
Go ahead.
We've dumped the core.
Welcome to the worst day
of my life.
TORRES:
Vorik, we have to get
those impulse engines
back on line.
You and Nicoletti
get started.
Yes, Lieutenant.
JANEWAY:
Report.
We're stopped dead.
The warp core is millions
of kilometers away by now.
And the impulse engines
are seriously damaged.
I can give you a few thrusters,
but that's about it.
How long before I can
have impulse power?
I can't give you
an estimate on that.
We're still assessing
the damage.
So much for opening
a transwarp conduit.
I sent the Borg
back to her alcove.
We won't be needing her
in here anymore.
At least
the core's still intact.
Tom, take a shuttle and find it.
See if you can tractor
it back to Voyager.
Yes, ma'am.
It'll be unstable.
It should be repaired
before he tries to put
a tractor beam on it.
Well then, you go with him.
Do whatever you have to.
Just get it back here
in one piece.
TORRES:
We're getting near
some random ion turbulence.
I'll change course
to avoid it.
I wonder what else
can go wrong today?
If we get this core back,
I'm going right to bed
and sleeping straight through
till tomorrow.
Get this day over with.
Well, look at it this way--
how much worse could it get?
Having to dump the warp core has
to be the low point of any day.
Maybe it's me.
Maybe I'm asking
for this trouble somehow.
Or maybe it's just
a string of bad luck.
Sensors have picked up
a polymetallic object...
could be the core.
That's the warp signature,
all right
but there's something else
out there... a ship.
According to sensors,
it has the same energy signature
as the Caatati ships.
Maybe they're guarding
it for us.
Right.
I see it.
PARIS:
What do they think
they're doing?
They're trying to put
a tractor beam on it.
This is the shuttle Cochrane
to the Caatati vessel.
Please respond.
CAATATI:
Don't come any closer.
We're performing
a salvage operation.
Oh, what a coincidence--
so are we.
I'm afraid we got here first.
Don't interfere
or we'll open fire.
Don't you realize
that core is highly unstable?
If you try to tractor it
like that
you could cause
an antimatter explosion.
They're not answering.
Idiots!
We have to stop them
from destroying the core.
I'm going to try to disrupt
their tractor beam.
It's working.
What was that?
They sent
an antimatter pulse
back through
our particle beam.
COMPUTER:
Warning. The structural
integrity field
has been compromised.
Now at 53% and falling.
Hull breach
in two minutes, twenty seconds.
Re-route power
from the propulsion
and weapons systems.
Warning. Hull breach in
two minutes, ten seconds.
No effect.
Warning. The structural
integrity field has collapsed.
Hull breach in two minutes.
We have to get out of here!
Warning. Hull breach in
one minute, fifty seconds...
Computer, send
a distress call to voyager.
Give them our coordinates.
Computer, respond.
The com systems must be down.
Transporters are still on-line.
Stand by to energize.
Energize.
Paris to Voyager.
Do you read me?
Please respond.
Paris to Voyager.
It's no use.
The com system in these suits
won't carry that far.
When they get
the impulse engines repaired
they'll come
looking for us.
Well, I don't plan
on just drifting here
hoping somebody will come along
and rescue us.
There must be something
we can do.
Agreed.
If we could interplex
the com systems in both suits
we might be able to create
a phased carrier wave.
Voyager would read
the signature
and know it's from us.
Good idea.
Let me access
your controls.
I thought you'd never ask.
TORRES:
That's it.
This would be a lot easier
if I had a hyper-spanner.
Hold still.
PARIS:
Why is it we have
to get beamed into space
in environmental suits
before I can initiate
first contact procedures?
TORRES:
Why is it that if we're alone
for more than 30 seconds
you start thinking
about contact?
PARIS:
That is not fair.
The other day in Engineering,
I must have gone four minutes
before I started thinking
about it.
Okay...
I'm ready to initiate
the carrier wave.
( loud whine )
Ah!
Sorry.
Better?
Yeah.
Let's hope
it's still that strong
by the time
it gets to Voyager.
( door beeping )
Come in.
Would you like tea
or coffee?
I have no need
to ingest liquids.
I still receive energy
from the Borg alcove.
My understanding is
that you're almost ready
to begin eating food.
That is what
the doctor says.
Why have you
asked me here?
Whenever there's
an accident on the ship--
even a minor one--
we investigate it
in order to minimize the chances
of its happening again.
A prudent course
of action.
I didn't have a chance
to talk to Lieutenant Torres
before she left the ship
so, I wanted to ask you
some questions
about what happened
in Engineering.
Sensor logs indicate
that tachyons
were leaking
into the warp core.
Do you have any idea
how it started?
No.
We had reconfigured the
deflector shield
to emit tachyon bursts.
The procedure
must've triggered the leak.
Who was controlling
the tachyon bursts?
Ensign Vorik.
What were you doing?
Monitoring
the transwarp frequencies.
And did you at any time
access deflector control?
You believe I'm responsible
for the accident?
That I deliberately
sabotaged the ship?
You're like the others.
You see me as a threat.
I won't lie to you.
Part of me is suspicious.
We've dealt
with tachyon fields before
and never had
this kind of problem.
Captain, I am unaccustomed
to deception.
Among the Borg,
it was impossible.
There were no lies,
no secrets,
and I assure you
I had nothing to do
with the accident
in Engineering.
I believe you. Thank you.
I am finding it
a difficult challenge
to integrate into this group.
It is full
of complex social structures
that are unfamiliar to me.
Compared with the Borg,
this crew is inefficient
and contentious,
but it is capable of...
surprising acts of compassion.
Unexpected acts of kindness
are common among our group.
That's one of the ways
we define ourselves.
Is there anything more?
Yes.
We still have to find out
what caused the tachyon leak.
Tell me what you remember
about the power fluctuations
in the propulsion system.
TORRES:
This isn't anything
like the simulations
we had at the academy.
They felt peaceful...
like floating
in the womb...
but right now,
I'm feeling a little sick
to my stomach.
You dropped out too soon.
In the third year,
there's a six-week course
of actual space walks
so you can get
used to them.
I never would've lasted
till the third year.
If I hadn't dropped out
they would've
asked me to leave.
I wish I'd known you then.
You'd have hated me.
I can't imagine a time
I wouldn't have
found you fascinating.
What the hell was that?
More ion turbulence.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Oxygen level
at 114 millibars.
My oxygen supply is leaking.
( gasping )
Warning. Oxygen level
at 93 millibars.
We'll have to share mine.
Are you getting air now?
( breathing deeply )
Yes.
Much better.
Thanks.
What's wrong?
The turbulence must
have damaged my suit, too.
I should have at least
24 hours worth of oxygen
but there's only about
a half hour left.
VORIK:
Engineering to Captain Janeway.
Yes, Ensign?
I am pleased to inform you that
impulse power should be restored
within the hour.
Good news. Let me know as soon
as the engines are on line.
Yes, Ma'am.
Captain, I believe I've found
the cause of the accident--
erratic fluctuations
in the ship's warp power.
When tachyon levels rose
to a resonant frequency
core pressure increased.
Then it was an accident.
( door beeping )
Come in.
Captain, we've picked up
a carrier wave
with a Starfleet signature.
I'd guess it's Tom and B'elanna,
but they're not
answering our hail.
They may be in trouble.
Soon as we get impulse power...
Tuvok to the Captain.
Can you come to the Bridge?
On my way.
We're being approached
by an armada of Caatati ships.
They're hailing us.
On screen.
Hello, Captain.
You've brought some friends.
Needy friends.
We're hoping
you'll offer us more supplies.
I made it clear last time
that we couldn't possibly
provide you
with enough for all your ships.
And I had to accept that
because your ship
is more powerful than ours
but the situation has changed,
hasn't it?
You seem to be
at a disadvantage now.
We have your warp core.
You can't escape.
I'm hoping that will
make you more generous.
We've given you
everything we can spare.
Return the core,
and we'll be on our way.
One of our ships might not seem
threatening to you,
but I assure you, 27 can
inflict considerable damage.
We are desperate.
Prepare to send us
food, weapons,
and your entire supply
of thorium.
And that Borg
you're protecting--
we want her, too.
There are many who would enjoy
a chance to repay one of them
for what they did to us.
PARIS:
I'm lowering
the oxygen ratio.
That should give us
a few more minutes.
( weakly ):
I'm feeling...
kind of groggy.
Oxygen deprivation.
And you're lowering it?
We have to try to make it
last as long as possible.
It's ironic, isn't it?
What?
Today...
the day of honor...
is the day that
I'm going to die.
We are not going to die.
Would you stop
talking like that?
We have to face up to it, Tom.
There's something
I've been wanting to ask you.
Well, now's the time.
When we first met...
you didn't have
a very high opinion of me.
That's putting it mildly.
I thought you were an arrogant,
self-absorbed pig.
( chuckles )
Flattery won't get you
any more oxygen.
Do you think I've changed?
A lot.
Now you're a stubborn,
domineering pig.
( labored breathing )
I'm just kidding.
There I go again...
just pushing you away.
You were right about me.
It's what I do...
push people away.
Well, it's a surefire way
of not getting hurt.
What a coward I am.
Shh...
Our weapons are more
powerful than theirs.
I say we fight.
Maybe if we give
them something.
JANEWAY:
Like what?
I can't imagine what
would satisfy them now.
SEVEN:
I will go.
They asked for me.
If I surrender myself,
perhaps they'll let you leave.
That's very generous,
but I will not turn
you over to them.
I was only offering
to do what would be best
for this group.
You're part of this group now,
and we're going to protect you.
It's time
to stop talking about this.
Tom and B'elanna are in trouble,
and we have to find them.
Tuvok, what's the status
of our weapons array?
Weapons are at the ready,
captain, but our shield strength
is extremely low.
We'll have to shut down
non-essential systems.
Reroute power
to the shields.
We're going to fight.
That might not be necessary.
Caatati technology is dependent
on thorium isotopes.
If they had enough, they could
become self-sustaining.
But we don't have that much
thorium to give them.
When the Borg
assimilated the Caatati
the survivors lost their ability
to replicate the isotopes.
But I have retained
that knowledge.
I could design an energy matrix
that would produce thorium
in large quantities.
If you've had this knowledge all
along, why didn't you say so?
I am not accustomed
to thinking that way.
Borg do not consider
giving technology away,
only assimilating it.
And what do you suppose
made you consider it now?
I am not certain.
Maybe... it was just
an unexpected act of kindness.
Work with Vorik
to build the energy matrix
while I convince the Caatati
there's a better way
out of this.
This matrix will produce
944 grams of thorium per day.
Now you can power
all your systems
and begin to rebuild
your replication technology.
Will you allow us
to leave?
One device isn't enough
for all our ships.
SEVEN:
Using this matrix
as a template,
you can construct
as many as you like.
We can provide you with
components and specifications.
You're free to go.
And thank you.
You're welcome.
COMPUTER:
Warning: Oxygen level
at 104 millibars.
Tom...
Hmm?
Come on.
Open your eyes.
Warning: Oxygen level
at 87 millibars.
I was having a dream.
There's something I have to say.
Me, too.
( labored breathing )
I'm glad
the last thing I'll see is you.
I've been a coward
about everything...
everything that really matters.
No. You're being
a little hard on yourself.
No.
I'm going to die...
without a shred of honor,
and for the first time
in my life,
that really bothers me.
So I have to tell you something.
Warning:
Oxygen level at 71 millibars.
I have to tell you the truth.
The truth about what?
I love you.
Say something.
You picked a great time
to tell me.
JANEWAY:
Voyager to Tom Paris.
Tom, do you read me? Respond.
( weakly: )
We're here.
Prepare to beam aboard.