( foliage rustling )
( insects chirping )
( bird calling )
MALE:
Don't move!
What's this?
We found him
in the trunks
a hundred footfalls
past Grove Yellow.
Arms?
None, sir.
These colors?
We didn't ask.
He's no Krady beast, is he?
No, sir, but he doesn't bear
Vori colors, either.
Hmm... his glimpse
is too tame to be a Kradin.
I hadn't fathomed
that, sir.
Well, fathom it now.
He's no nemesis,
is he?
I'm not certain
what he is, sir.
Weren't you drilled
to fathom the nemesis?
Yes, sir.
And we abhor none
but the nemesis,
do we?
No, sir.
None but the nemesis.
Then set him loose.
Didn't you hear, novice?
Thanks.
Go take
provisions.
I'm sorry, sir...
Go.
I take it you're
in charge here.
Team Leader Brone,
Fourth Vori Defense Contingent.
Commander Chakotay
of the Starship Voyager.
Very sorry
for my defenders.
They're new
to the clash
and glimpse the nemesis
all around them.
The clash?
You're at war.
You've strayed into
the fullness of it.
That explains why
my shuttle came under fire.
One of my defenders
glimpsed a vessel
falling in Grove Yellow.
Must've been yours.
Why fly so close
to this sphere?
I was on a survey mission.
I picked up traces
of omicron radiation
in your atmosphere, so I
slowed down to take a look.
As soon as I did that,
I came under attack.
I lost helm control
and had to make an emergency
transport to the surface.
It'll be the Kradin
who fired at you.
The Kradin?
Our nemesis.
I see.
Well, I tried to explain that
I had no hostile intentions,
but they just kept shooting.
The nemesis crave
supremacy in the air.
They fire on any craft that
doesn't show Kradin colors.
I tried to contact my ship,
but my communicator's
not working.
All dispatching
in the clash zone
has been suppressed.
I have to find my vessel.
Maybe it's salvageable.
That's little likely.
We're ordered to cluster
with the Seventh Contingent
two new lights from now.
They'll have means
to signal your people.
You can make the walk
with us to meet them.
I appreciate the offer,
but I can't wait two days.
I have to find my vessel now.
It wouldn't be sharp
to return to the trunks.
The nemesis is
everywhere there.
Then I'll have to do my best
to steer clear of them.
If your tactic
won't change...
It won't.
It's sharper to wait
for the new light.
Then I'll take
your advice and wait.
( quiet conversations )
Well done.
( sighs )
Provisions?
It's not so savory.
Thanks. I'm sure
it'll be fine.
They call me Rafin.
Chakotay.
Pleased to meet you.
In the trunks, di...
did you glimpse any?
Any what?
Krady beasts.
No, I didn't.
Rafin's never glimpsed
the face of the nemesis, either.
Have you, Rafin?
No.
It's my first walk
in the clash zone.
You'll glimpse them
in the Soonafter.
When you do, you'll fathom
there's no heart thumping
beneath their flesh.
How many beasts will you send
to the Wayafter, Rafin?
I... I couldn't say.
Me, I'll nullify one
for each brother and cousin
that I've lost.
And then one more after.
True or not,
my allies?
SOLDIERS:
True.
So I ask you
again, Rafin.
How many
will you nullify?
As man... as many
as I'm able.
You've got the trembles.
If you don't wrestle
your trembles to rages, ally,
the nemesis will nullify you.
This nemesis of yours--
why do you
call them beasts?
It's told they all wear
the same horrid face.
Their flesh...
is gnarled and blistery
like the rotting trunks.
Their glimpses
flame like fire.
And if you dare near enough,
their breath stinks of muck.
You know, sometimes
people say terrible things
about their enemies,
to make them seem worse
than they really are.
There might be some
young Kradin soldier out there
who's more afraid of you
than you are of him.
Nemesis wasn't scared
to fume my village...
nor scared to nullify my cousins
and brothers in their sleep.
And my old mother's mother,
too...
who never told an unkind word,
nor nullified an insect
in all her days and nights
on this sphere.
That's pretty rough.
And who but a Krady beast
would leave the nullified bodies
of mine and ours upturned...
so they'll never descend
to the gloried Wayafter.
What do you mean by "upturned"?
Which of you will walk
with Chakotay
to find his craft
when the new light comes?
I appreciate the offer,
but I'll be fine on my own.
You don't fathom the trunks
and you don't carry arms.
One of my defenders
will walk with you.
Which will it be?
You, Rafin?
S-Sir, I... I...
NAMON:
I'll walk with
the stranger, sir.
If any beast
comes to clash,
I'll nullify the beast.
Well told, Namon.
Now close your
glimpses, Defenders...
and dream of your
sisters and mothers.
Have you never nullified
another, stranger?
Killing's the worst thing
I've ever had to do.
Then the nemesis
you nullified
wasn't half so beastly
as the Kradin.
Maybe not.
In their glimpses,
we're less than nothing.
They flame our homes,
take our plantings...
make playthings
of our sisters.
If you were a Vori,
you'd crave to drive them
from this sphere
just as I do.
Maybe I would
if they did things
like that
to the people I loved.
But on the sphere
I come from,
we try to find
other ways
to resolve differences--
peaceful solutions,
negotiations.
You don't fathom
the nemesis.
No. I suppose
I don't.
Beg the Power
you believe in
that you never will.
The light will be old soon.
We'd be sharp to cluster
with the others.
In a few minutes.
We should be
getting close.
You'd be sharp
to do my tellings.
Go back
if you want to.
I've got to keep looking.
No, wait.
I pledged
to walk with you.
Glimpse there.
Doesn't look like there's
much left of my shuttle.
You'll have to make
the walk with us
to the Seventh
Contingent.
( brush rustling )
( gasps )
Don't make me kill you!
( gunshots )
How is he?
Nullified.
BRONE:
We beg peace from the Power
who made us Vori
and we commend
our brother, Namon,
to the gloried Wayafter.
What's this?
Namon's coverings.
Shouldn't they go to his family
or someone he was close to?
It's a long walk
to the clustermark.
It's sharper to blend
with the trunks.
Your fleet colors will
get us all nullified.
I'm sorry about
what happened to Namon.
The nemesis has nullified
mine and ours in the before
and will in the now.
But in the Soonafter...
we'll send them flying
from this sphere
and go back to our
sisters and mothers.
Take it.
This isn't my war.
I'm not planning
to shoot anybody.
If we greet the nemesis
in the trunks, you'll fire
like the rest.
As long as you're with us,
you do my tellings, fathom?
Fathom.
Rafin.
Yes, sir?
Drill Chakotay
to fire Vori arms.
( gunshot )
Now you.
Your glimpse is too low.
With these arms,
it's sharper
to aim higher
than the mark.
You're good.
Don't mock me.
I was paying you
a compliment.
It is one matter
to fire at clay marks,
but much another
to nullify the nemesis.
That's what Namon told,
and he told the truth
before he went
to the gloried Wayafter.
He was right.
Killing's not easy.
Risking my own days
and nights
to drive the nemesis
from our sphere...
that should be as
easy as a long sleep.
Who taught you that?
My brothers and uncles
who were in the clash...
Brone, my driller...
and Namon, my ally...
who was nullified
because of me.
You think it's your
fault that Namon died?
If I didn't have
the coward's trembles,
I would have walked with you
in the trunks...
and it would be me and not he
who went to the Wayafter.
You weren't the one who
pulled the trigger, Rafin,
and there's no shame in
being afraid of fighting.
Having the trembles is natural.
How do you fathom that?
Because I've been
in battle before,
fighting to free my people
from a nemesis called
the Cardassians.
These Cardassians...
were they beasts?
Let's just say they
weren't very friendly.
The point is,
even though I believed
in what we were doing,
I always felt fear
before a fight.
But you wrestled your trembles
to rages, didn't you?
I guess I did,
but that doesn't mean...
I was told to drill you,
Chakotay,
but it's you
who've drilled me--
drilled me to fathom the rages.
Brone.
What is it?
I don't know.
Neck-strapped and upturned.
Left to be cooked by the glare.
He's one of yours?
By his coverings,
he's of the Seventh Contingent.
Likely a scoutwalker.
Desecrated by the Kradin.
He'll never turn his face
to the Wayafter.
We're 300 footfalls
from the clustermark.
Signal the Seventh.
Again.
Why don't they answer?
Is it possible they moved
their camp for some reason?
Little likely.
You two fastwalk
to the clustermark
and glimpse
what you can.
Sir.
What?
Let me go.
Well told, novice.
Keep your top low
and your glimpse wide.
( footsteps approaching )
Sir!
What have you glimpsed?
The Seventh Contingent, sir,
nullified.
What? All of them?
At least 20 defenders
and that's not the
whole terrible of it.
They're all...
they're all...
Tell it, Rafin.
They're all how?
Like him, sir.
Upturned.
Staked to the dirt
and upturned.
Those motherless Krady beasts.
Do you glimpse the fullness
of it now, stranger?
Yes. I think I do.
Now you fathom why we name
them beasts and not men.
I'm sorry.
We're much more
than sorry...
aren't we, Defenders?
SOLDIERS:
Yes, sir!
The nemesis
wants your plantings.
SOLDIERS:
True.
He wants your homes.
He wants your sisters,
but does it suffice him
to nullify you?
SOLDIERS:
No!
No. He craves
to shame you,
mock you, keep you from
the gloried Wayafter!
We're wearied of it,
aren't we?
SOLDIERS:
Yes, sir!
We're wrestled to the rages
for it, aren't we?!
SOLDIERS:
Yes, sir!
And we're not going
to swallow it--
not in the now,
or in the Soonafter!
( gunshots )
Assault!
Sly yourselves and fire back!
( groans )
Motherless beasts!
Rafin, no! Stay down!
I'll nullify you all!
( grunts )
( gunfire continues )
Hold on.
I'm going to get
you out of here.
( cries out )
Please...
turn my face to the... Wayafter.
( breathing stops )
( gunshots, soldiers yelling)
( panting )
( distant voices )
A defender.
Mark, neighbors.
A defender!
( all talking )
Welcome to Larhana settlement,
gloried defender.
You're brightly greeted.
Captain's Log,
stardate 51082.4.
After searching
for more than two days,
we've finally located
what's left
of Commander Chakotay's
shuttle.
I can only hope the Commander
has fared better
than his vessel.
According to the Ambassador,
Commander Chakotay's shuttle
was hit by enemy fire
and crash-landed somewhere
on the southernmost continent.
Right in the middle
of the war zone.
I'm afraid so.
Can we get a lock on him?
Too much radiation from weapons.
We can't scan the surface.
Which means, we don't know
if he's still alive.
Why don't we assume
that he still is?
I should have
gone with him.
It's not your fault, Tom.
We couldn't have
anticipated this.
What we've got to do now
is figure out
how to deal with it.
B'Elanna, try to modify
the scanners,
cut through the interference.
Aye, Captain.
Neelix, what do you know
about this war?
It's vicious.
Ambassador Treen's people
have been defending themselves
against a particularly
savage aggressor
for more than a decade.
Is the Ambassador willing
to help us find Chakotay?
He's willing,
but he may not be able.
His resources
are extremely limited
and the situation
on the surface is chaotic.
NEELIX:
But he's assured me
that if his troops
do find Chakotay,
he'll receive medical attention
and be transported
to the nearest command post.
Let's hope he
doesn't meet up
with these
"savage aggressors" first.
Captain, let me lead
a team down there
and bring him back.
I understand how you feel, Tom,
but let's take it
one step at a time.
Tuvok, recontact
Ambassador Treen.
Ask for any tactical support
he's willing to provide--
maps, weapons analyses,
intelligence reports.
Before I risk
anyone else's life,
I want to know exactly
what we're getting
ourselves into.
By your coverings,
you're a novice defender.
Do I tell the truth?
Listen, there's been
a misunderstanding.
I'm not a defender.
My shuttle was shot down
by the Kradin
and I landed in the clash zone.
I met up
with one of your patrols.
They gave me this uniform.
Which Contingent?
The Fourth.
The Fourth?
They're sturdy clashers.
Tell us-- did you
and your allies
drive the nemesis
from the trunks?
We put up a brave fight.
FEMALE:
Then you're
a gloried defender
even if you claim not to be.
Marna tells the
truth, Chakotay.
You are welcome
among my neighbors.
Thank you.
That's very kind.
Do you crave anything more?
Drink? Warm coverings?
What I really need is
some communications equipment
to contact my crew.
We have no means
to signal your people.
MARNA:
The Kradin drove us
from our homes
and plantings and took
all the machinery we had.
Do you know
where I might find someplace
with communications equipment?
The re-stock unit.
Can you tell me
how to get there?
It's not very near--
at least 10,000 footfalls
through the thick
of the trunks.
Then I'd better get started.
The new light is coming.
Rest till then.
Yes, please,
Chakotay.
Rest until
the new light.
I think I will.
Come, neighbors.
Let's give Defender
Chakotay some quiet.
I wanted to know
if you crave more.
No, thank you.
Oh.
But it was delicious.
And the blossoms?
Do you like them?
I planted them myself.
They're very pretty.
I've heard tellings
that the Kradin
leave our nullied defenders
upturned.
Is it true?
You can tell me.
Penno says I'm too small
to be told, but I'm not.
It's true the Kradin
don't respect your beliefs.
The Kradin are beasty.
I don't fathom
why they flamed our homes
nor why they crave
to nully us all.
I don't, either.
We never took
their plantings.
We never nullied
their brothers.
So why do they hate us?
I wish I could tell you.
Hate's not something
I understand very well.
My brother's a defender, too.
Really?
He left for the clash
two plantings before.
I was much smaller then.
He was sturdy and pleasing
to glimpse in his colors.
Like you.
Maybe you've
glimpsed him.
He's called Daryo.
There are
a lot of soldiers in the war.
I only met a few of them.
He's a team leader
of the Seventh
Defense Contingent.
The Seventh?
Are you sure
he was with the Seventh?
They're very sturdy
in the clash.
Have you heard of them?
The patrol I was with
was supposed
to rendezvous with them.
Why didn't you?
You would have glimpsed him.
We were ambushed
before we had the chance.
But when you go back
to the clash
likely you'll glimpse
Daryo then.
You could take a letter to him.
I'm not going back
to the clash zone.
I've got to get
to the re-stock unit
so I can contact my ship.
Then you can bring my letter
to the re-stock unit.
Likely some defender there
can take it to Daryo.
Will you do it?
Please?
I'll go write it now
before the new light comes.
( sighing )
CHAKOTAY:
I wish you a good day.
Thank you.
Provisions for
your long walk.
Walk well,
Defender Chakotay.
Thank you both.
You've all been very kind.
Writings for
my brother.
You'll be sure
he gets them?
I'll do my best.
Your best
will be enough.
The pretty smell
of the blossoms
will hold the
nemesis far away.
Then you'd better
keep one for yourself.
( aircraft overhead )
( explosions )
( people yelling,
children crying )
FEMALE:
Father!
( crying, yelling continue )
Offer no opposition
or you'll be nullified.
No evidence of
cellular residue
on the shuttle wreckage,
so there's a chance
Chakotay survived the crash.
Well, unfortunately,
the wreckage was found
inside enemy territory.
So there is
also a chance
he's been captured
or killed by the nemesis.
There you go looking
on the bright side again, Tuvok.
What's this "nemesis"?
It is the term
Ambassador Treen's people
use to identify their enemy.
Apparently, they're vicious.
They shoot
without warning,
use biochemical weapons,
routinely massacre civilians.
If we run into them,
it's safe to say
they won't be hanging out
a welcome sign.
I want a team on the surface
as soon as possible.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Tuvok, let's get moving.
I must caution you both.
My tactical analysis
does not bode well
for the success
of such a mission.
Given the situation
in the battle zone,
there is
a very high probability
that an away team
will sustain heavy casualties.
Are you saying we should
just abandon Chakotay?
On the contrary.
I suppose you've come up
with an alternative plan?
Indeed.
I have concluded
that the least risky
course of action is for
a single crew member
to make the infiltration,
accompanied by
a commando unit
that Ambassador Treen
has agreed to provide.
Fine with me.
When do I leave?
Something tells me that's
not what Tuvok has in mind.
Naturally, I am
the logical person
to carry out this mission.
Naturally.
Get down there!
Chakotay!
I heard the explosions.
I came back to help.
What did the Kradin
do to you?
They interrogated me.
Where's your grandfather?
I don't know.
He's very gray,
and his heart's not sturdy.
He needs me to tend him.
You!
You! I want to talk
to your superior!
Hey! I'm talking to you.
I want to know
what you've done
with this girl's grandfather.
He's old and needs medical...
( grunts )
Chakotay!
Penno always tells
it'll be brighter
when the new light comes.
Your grandfather
is a wise man.
That's right.
Now get some sleep.
You'll tend me, won't you?
No matter what comes
in the Soonafter?
Close your glimpses...
and dream
of your gloried brother.
( two gunshots )
KRADIN:
Move along, Vori.
VORI:
Don't shoot.
( babies crying )
( worried voices )
OLD VORI:
We're coming.
KRADIN:
Move along!
Where are they
taking them?
I don't know.
They'll be fastwalked
to the extermination facility.
Why?
Because they're gray
and too long-lived
and the Kradin think them
unfit for toiling.
They won't make good servers,
like us.
Penno!
Karya!
Where are they taking you?
Be sturdy,
my daughter's daughter.
Who's going to tend you?
We'll glimpse each other again
in the Wayafter.
Set him loose!
Karya!
KRADIN:
Be still.
Keep your hands off her!
Don't touch her!
Halt!
What's the matter, pretty one?
Set my mother's
father loose!
Is that the
man you mean?
No! Karya!
Please!
Set him loose!
You don't want
to see him suffer, do you,
pretty one?
No.
Don't worry.
The old Vori's suffering'll
be over soon enough.
No!
Penno!
Take this
screeching waif
to the extermination
facility.
No. Chakotay.
Set me loose!
Chakotay,
help me!
You motherless beast!
Are Ambassador Treen
and his soldiers
ready to beam aboard?
Aye, Captain.
Energize.
Welcome aboard,
Ambassador.
Thank you for agreeing
to help us find our crewman.
Your thanks
are unnecessary, Captain.
Any victim of our
bloodthirsty nemesis the Vori
will always find friends
among the Kradin people.
( panting )
Chakotay...
calm now.
I'll set you loose.
Sorry to leave you
upturned so long...
but I had to shroud
myself in the trunks
till the Kradin
walked on.
The villagers
from Larhana settlement?
They were fastwalked
through the trunks.
And your defenders?
All nullified.
Thank you for
coming back for me.
You put yourself at risk.
And you, Chakotay, clashed
beside us against the Kradin
though you're a stranger
to this sphere.
I glimpsed you chancing
your days and nights
to save Rafin
from our nemesis.
You tell the truth
when you name them beasts.
What will you do
now that your men are gone?
Join with
the Fifth Contingent.
They're trying to
free the villagers.
It doesn't go
brightly for them.
I'll come with you.
No. I'll bring
you to command.
You can signal
your people.
That can wait
till the Soonafter.
In the now...
you need my help
to nullify the nemesis.
Backwalk!
The nemesis is nearing!
It's sharper to backwalk!
( explosion )
( Brone groaning )
( gunfire continues )
Brone!
AMPLIFIED VOICE:
Vori soldiers!
You are surrounded.
Lay down your arms
and surrender.
Hold your fire!
You'll have to
nullify me first!
Hold your fire,
Commander Chakotay.
Do not fire, Commander.
How do you know my name?
I am Lieutenant Tuvok.
Tuvok?
Don't walk any closer.
I've come to bring
you back to Voyager.
Nullify him, Chakotay!
It's a Kradin tactic.
I assure you,
Commander,
this is no ruse.
It is Lieutenant Tuvok.
Don't you recognize me?
He's the nemesis!
You're a Kradin beast.
You destroyed
that village,
nullified Penno;
took away Karya.
She was only a child!
They've brainwashed you,
Commander.
Look closer.
Try to recall.
Your shuttle was shot down.
These people-- the Vori--
they captured you.
No. They rescued me.
That is what they want you
to believe.
But they have been
indoctrinating you, training you
to fight their war.
Take one more step
and I'll nullify you.
You are Commander Chakotay
of the Starship Voyager.
You are a scientist,
an explorer.
You are not a killer.
Tuvok.
Yes, Commander.
How can you
wear those colors?
The Kradin...
they're beasts, murderers.
On the contrary--
they are the ones
who helped us locate you.
We tracked you
to a Vori training camp.
We infiltrated the facility,
but you were gone.
They had already
brought you here
to fight this battle.
Before today, nothing you
experienced here was real.
It is the method the Vori use
to conscript and train soldiers.
I don't believe you!
I will prove it to you
if you will lower your weapon.
( distant voices )
Do you recognize
this place?
It's Larhana
settlement.
A defender.
Mark, neighbors!
( all talking )
Defender.
Karya.
Welcome to Larhana settlement,
gloried defender.
You're brightly greeted.
Captain's Log,
stardate 51096.5.
Although Lieutenant Tuvok
has managed
to bring Commander Chakotay
safely back to the ship,
it may be some time
before his psychological wounds
are fully healed.
My guess is the Vori used
a combination
of mind control techniques,
including
photometric projections,
heightened emotional stimuli
and highly sophisticated
psychotropic manipulation.
From the condition
of your hypothalamus,
I'd say they had you
so mixed up
they could have convinced you
your own mother was a turnip.
Everything I experienced
was some sort of simulation?
Except for the battle
you were fighting
when Tuvok found you.
Apparently, attacking
the simulated commandant
marked your graduation
from basic training.
And the men I fought beside--
none of them was real?
Namon and Rafin weren't killed
in front of me?
As far as we can tell, they
were part of the simulation.
The idea was
to make you bond
with your fellow soldiers
as well as the villagers,
so their deaths
would enrage you.
Why me?
Luck of the draw.
You happened to be
passing through their space
and you were as promising
a recruit as anyone else.
We've been told
the Vori have dozens
of these training facilities
where they conscript
their own people
and any aliens
they're able to capture.
DOCTOR:
In short, Commander,
you've been subjected
to a highly sophisticated form
of propaganda.
Then the Kradin don't kill
innocent civilians?
They don't desecrate
the Vori's dead?
I don't know.
But the Kradin accuse the Vori
of the same kinds of atrocities.
I cared about the Vori,
but I hated the Kradin.
I wanted to kill
every one of them.
Evidently, that was the point.
( door opens )
NEELIX:
Captain.
Ambassador Treen would like
to have a word
with the Commander.
I wish to tell you
how pleased
our people are
to hear of your recovery.
I'm only sorry we weren't able
to rescue you sooner
from our nemesis.
Have I said something wrong?
I don't know.
If you'll excuse me, Captain.
Chakotay?
I wish it were as
easy to stop hating
as it was to start.