( beeping )
( console beeping )
To any vessels within range,
I hope this message reaches you.
I'm an HD-25
isomorphic projection.
There's been an accident.
My crew is dead.
I'm alone.
Please, help me.
So we rigged
the security console,
so that every time Tuvok
accessed the internal sensors,
it would play
a little message...
"Live long
and prosper."
PARIS:
No matter what button
he pushed:
"Live long and prosper."
KIM:
Naturally, no one
was available
to fix the malfunction, so...
So Tuvok had to stretch
his Vulcan patience to the limit
for the rest of the day.
I swear you could hear
him grinding his teeth
from across the Bridge.
( laughter )
Just when he thought
it was over,
when he went back
to his quarters,
and ordered a cup
of Vulcan tea,
the replicator says...
"Live long and prosper!"
( laughter )
The first time
I met Tuvok,
he dressed me down in front
of three Starfleet Admirals
for failing to observe
proper tactical procedures
during my first command.
My human ego took
a little bruising, but...
of course, he was right.
Over the past nine years,
I've come to rely
on his insightful
and unfailingly logical advice.
For outstanding service
as Chief Tactical
and Security Officer,
it's my pleasure
to grant you the rank
of Lieutenant Commander.
Congratulations, Tuvok.
Thank you, Captain.
Had I known
this commendation
entailed ritual humiliation,
I might have declined.
However, I accept
it with gratitude
and will honor
the responsibility
that comes with it.
During my three years on
Voyager,
I have grown to respect
a great many of you.
Others, I have learned
to tolerate.
As your
Tactical Officer,
I will continue
to do my best
to ensure a safe passage home.
As a Vulcan, I share
the following sentiment:
Live long and prosper.
JANEWAY:
Bravo! Well-deserved.
B'Elanna.
( anxious laughter )
This is ridiculous.
It's been three days,
and we haven't said
a word to each other.
I know, I know.
We have to talk.
About what you said,
I mean...
the part about
being in love with me.
I realize you were suffering
from oxygen deprivation,
and we were literally
seconds away from death,
so I know you probably
didn't mean it.
Oh, no, no.
I meant it.
But I don't expect you
to reciprocate, really.
Uh, you can just pretend
that I didn't say it.
In fact, let's just forget
that I even said anything.
Shut up.
I really--
DOCTOR:
Mr. Paris,
there you are.
TORRES:
I was just leaving. Lieutenant.
What can I do for you, Doc?
The Captain
has authorized me
to recruit someone with
advanced medical training
to help out in Sick Bay.
Unfortunately, the most
qualified crew member is you.
You want me to be
the new nurse?
If that's the title
you prefer.
It will only
be temporary,
three duty shifts
a week.
Report to Sick Bay
at 0600 hours.
Bring a tricorder
and a smile.
KIM:
What kind
of modifications?
We'd like to enhance
the Astrometrics Lab.
It hasn't been upgraded since
Voyager left Spacedock.
I'll start right away.
I've assigned Seven of
Nine to work with you.
She's agreed
to provide us
with all the navigational
data for this area
she acquired during
her time with the Borg.
Is there a problem?
No. No problem.
Try to make her feel
like part of the team.
Right.
Part of the team.
Have you made arrangements with
the Arritheans for tomorrow?
The delegate says
he's looking forward
to trading
with such an advanced starship.
You have done an excellent job
preparing for this mission.
I think we should
consider this
your first official
assignment as Ambassador.
Ensign Culhane to the Captain.
Janeway here.
We are receiving
an automated distress call
five light-years from here.
You might want
to bring the Doctor.
I'm an HD-25
isomorphic projection.
There's been an accident.
My crew is dead.
I'm alone.
Please, help me.
He's a hologram.
We've got to help him.
Ensign, track the source
of the transmission.
Once we find his ship,
I'll lead an away team.
I don't recall
giving you a promotion today.
Oh... well, I'm
the obvious choice
to provide assistance
to a holographic being.
Doctor, I don't want you leaving
Voyager
unless it's
absolutely necessary.
I'm still concerned about
damaging your mobile emitter.
I understand.
But if this
is a hologram--
one of my own kind,
so to speak--
I'd like to meet him,
study him.
I'll bring Lieutenant Torres,
just to be safe.
She knows more about my emitter
than anyone.
The rest of us will meet
with the Arritheans.
We'll see you there
when you're finished.
Thank you, Captain.
( sighs )
Seven?
I am here.
Am I to work with you?
Oh, hi. Yes.
Uh, I thought we'd start
in Jefferies tube 32-B,
enhance the astrometric sensors,
if that's okay with you.
Unless this is a bad time.
Maybe I can come back later.
Ensign Kim, you seem...
apprehensive.
No, not at all.
The last time
we worked together,
I struck you at the base
of your skull
and attempted
to contact the collective.
These things happen.
I assure you,
it will not happen again.
That's good to know.
I've designed
new navigational sensors.
Some of the alphanumerics
are Borg.
No problem.
I always wanted
to learn Borg.
That is difficult to believe.
I was kidding.
It was a joke.
You know... humor.
I understand
the concept of humor.
It may not be apparent,
but I am often amused
by human behavior.
( wry laughter )
( sighs )
( Doctor sighs )
TORRES:
Relax, Doctor.
I'm sure
we'll find the ship.
That's not what I'm
concerned about.
I've been questioning the wisdom
of leaving Mr. Paris in charge
of my Sick Bay.
Tom will do fine.
He's a very responsible guy.
Well, I suppose you'd
know better than I would.
What's that supposed to mean?
You seem to have become
good friends.
Let's get one thing straight.
I don't appreciate you
or anyone else
speculating about the kind
of friendships I have.
Or who I have them with.
Sorry. I didn't realize
I'd struck a nerve.
Perhaps you'd like
a tranquilizer.
( console beeping )
There it is.
That's his ship?
Try hailing him.
No response.
Life signs?
A few energy readings,
but they're erratic.
Propulsion and main power
are down.
We're approaching
transporter range.
Hello?
Is anyone here?
We're here to help you.
No signs of life?
Not yet.
I'd like to check
your mobile emitter,
make sure you made it
through the transport okay.
For a Klingon, you have
a decent bedside manner.
Thanks.
DOCTOR:
I wonder what kind
of bedside manner
Mr. Paris
will exhibit.
That was a rhetorical
question, Lieutenant.
Your holographic matrix
is stable,
but let me check your
emitter's power cells.
DOCTOR:
You might want to consider
a career in medicine.
( clattering )
Where the hell
did this come--?
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
You sent the distress call?
Yes, yes. Yes, that's me.
It was me.
And you, you're an isomorph,
like myself?
We use the term
"hologram."
( sighs )
Holo... gram.
And you, y-you're
a hologram too?
No.
You're organic.
Uh... that's one way
of putting it, yes.
It looks like your program
is fairly compatible
with our holographic
technology.
Can you tell me
where I can access
your projection controls?
Why?
You're obviously
malfunctioning.
Maybe I can repair you.
Oh, of course.
I'd appreciate that.
Over there, you can
access my systems
from that console.
What happened here?
Oh, it was terrible,
just terrible.
You see, we left Seros
eight months ago--
Seros, that's
our home planet--
with a crew of six.
All isomorphic
projections?
No, just me.
I'm an HD-25
maintenance unit
with extreme-hazard
clearance.
I'm responsible for
cleaning the reactor core,
ejecting antimatter waste, that
sort of thing.
W-When the crew got sick, there
was nothing I could do.
I'm-I'm not designed
for medical functions.
I-I... I...
Try to calm down.
Explain what happened
one step at a time.
Two of the crew members
left to survey a planet.
When they came back,
they'd been infected
by a deadly virus.
It spread quickly
to the other
organics on board
and one by one...
well, I watched
them all die.
And then things started
to malfunction here.
I have limited knowledge
of the controls.
I don't know
what I would've done
if you hadn't come.
I think I've stabilized
your program,
but I'll need access
to your primary isomatrix.
Where is it?
On the lower deck.
You shouldn't go down there.
Why not?
Too dangerous.
That deck's been flooded
with antimatter radiation.
Organic flesh would
disintegrate within seconds.
You can access my isomatrix from
this deck.
There's an interface junction
in that compartment.
Thanks.
Mind if I run
a quick diagnostic?
What's your name?
I don't have a name.
It's a long story.
I'd like
to hear it...
and everything
else about you.
I'm ready to supply power
to the enhanced sensors.
What? Already?
Yes.
You believe that my work
is unsuitable.
Of course not. Just checking.
Standard procedure.
I may no longer possess
Borg perfection,
but my experience as a drone
has taught me
to be efficient
and precise.
Actually, you misaligned
this optical assembly.
Impossible.
Take a look. It's off by .5
degrees.
It must have been my humanity
reasserting itself.
I will correct the error.
So, what do you do for fun
down in Cargo Bay 2?
Fun?
You know, relaxation,
entertainment
during your
off hours?
I regenerate in my alcove,
I study
the Starfleet database...
or I contemplate my existence.
That's a lot of time
by yourself.
It is.
The optical assembly
is properly aligned.
I'm ready to access
the main power supply.
After you.
Wait! What are you doing?!
There are five million gigawatts
running through there!
The exoskeleton on this limb
can withstand it.
That's all well and good,
but there are safety procedures
we've got to follow.
Your procedures
are a waste of time.
Maybe so, but you've been
assigned to me,
and I say we do this
by the book, all right?
All right.
Well...
now that we've got
that cleared up.
You can use this emitter
to go anywhere?
Well, my Captain has imposed
a few restrictions,
but I'm free
to leave Sick Bay,
join away missions,
take a stroll.
Extraordinary.
I-I-I've, I've never left
this vessel before.
And until the crew got sick,
I never even left
the antimatter storage chamber.
Do you know what it's like
to spend your life trapped
inside a tiny room?
Not knowing what's
beyond the door?
What the world
is really like?
Nobody coming to see you
or talk to you
unless they want
something?
Actually, I know exactly
what it's like.
When I was first activated,
I was regarded
as little more than
a talking tricorder.
I had to ask for the
privileges I deserved:
the right to be included
in crew briefings,
the ability to turn
my program on and off.
It's taken some time,
but I believe I've earned
the respect of the
crew as an equal.
An equal?
I've also been pursuing
personal interests:
art, literature, music.
Perhaps you could do the same.
Oh, no, no, no.
My programmers on Seros
would never allow that.
Then you'll convince them. Maybe
they'll appreciate
how well you've coped
with this situation.
How you've managed
to find help.
Think about it.
You've already exceeded
the sum of your subroutines.
What are you doing?
Nothing. Oh, nothing.
I'm just sterilizing the ship.
I'm fastidious about germs.
I know that must sound strange
coming from an
artificial being.
Not at all.
I've been known to act
a little strangely myself.
Hungry?
You're organic.
You require nutrients.
They're only rations,
but our crew liked them.
TORRES:
Careful!
That's an isomagnetic conduit.
You could destabilize
your matrix.
Of course.
How stupid of me.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have barged in here.
That's all right.
I could use a break.
Thank you.
You nibble...
like a fish.
I'll take that
as a compliment.
Oh, it is.
I've never seen a fish before,
not a real one,
but I've read about them
on our database.
Fish aren't like other organics.
They're more passive, I think,
most of them.
And so clean.
Um, is there anything I can do
to help with repairs?
Well, as soon as
I'm done with lunch,
you could help me access
your primary matrix.
Gladly.
Is something wrong?
Seeing the ship ripped apart
like this, it's...
I guess I can't help feeling
a kind of affinity
for this vessel.
It sustains my existence
and sometimes I feel
like it's a part of my body...
my soul.
That probably sounds
silly to you.
No. No, I understand
how you feel.
You couldn't possibly understand
how I feel, you're organic.
You exist apart from your ship.
"I understand how you feel."
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to offend you.
You're the one who's trapped,
not me.
You spend your entire life
stuck inside a biological cage
of flesh and bone
and blood.
Right. I'm going to go
give the Doctor an update.
I exist as pure energy,
but you depend on food
and water to survive.
Frankly, I find it disgusting.
Look at you. Look at you!
Grinding up bits of plants
and animals with your teeth.
Secreting saliva
to force it down your esophagus
into a pit
of digestive acids.
You can't even stand
to think about it yourself.
What a repulsive creature
you are, constantly
shedding your skin
and hair,
leaving your oily sweat
on everything you touch.
You think
that you are the height
of intellect in the universe,
but you are no better
than any filthy animal,
and I am ashamed
to be made in your image!
My apologies.
I have acquired some hostility
toward organics.
It was not meant for you.
I was treated quite badly
by the crew here.
I'm sorry to hear that...
um, but you have to realize
that... we're here to help you.
Thanks for the rations.
We've got a problem.
Oh?
I think there's a problem
with our isomorph,
and I'm not talking
about his emitters.
Explain.
I just spent
the last ten minutes
hearing his views
on biological life.
Let's just say
they're a bit unconventional.
Did you realize
that we organics
are a bunch of inferior,
disgusting animals?
Now that you mention it.
He started ranting
about how much
he despises organics.
I didn't think I was going to
get out of there
without a fight.
I will admit he is
somewhat socially inept.
Inept? He's a lunatic.
That is hardly a sound
medical diagnosis.
He has also
been lying to us.
I just ran a tricorder scan
of the lower deck,
the one he said
was flooded with radiation.
Well, it's not.
Why would he lie
about that?
I don't know.
Maybe he doesn't want us
to go down there.
Maybe he's hiding
something.
I understand your
concerns, Lieutenant.
I've been talking
to him, as well,
and I recognize
that he has some...
behavioral difficulties.
But imagine what
he's been through:
Trapped in a room no bigger
than a storage compartment.
And he's had almost no
interaction with organic beings.
It's only natural he's developed
problems communicating,
even a little resentment.
Do you recall my own behavior
when I was first activated?
How could I forget? You were a
major pain in the--
My point is... I, too,
was somewhat alienated
from the rest of the crew.
It took me a few days
to master the social graces.
I realize that he
is a fellow hologram,
and that you are
committed to helping him,
but I want the ability
to shut down his program
if I have to.
If you really feel
that's necessary.
I'm going to search
the lower deck,
see if I can access
his primary isomatrix.
You keep him occupied
until I get back.
I don't think
he'd appreciate
a filthy animal like me
snooping around--
Am I interrupting?
No. Actually,
I was, uh, just leaving.
I'd like you
to meet someone.
Doctor,
this is Spectrum.
A holographic fish?
Magnificent, isn't he?
So peaceful and so content.
I programmed him
to keep me company.
Well, don't you
have a pet?
Oh, it wouldn't
be appropriate,
not in a medical
environment.
They wouldn't let me
have one, either.
I had to hide him.
He's very lifelike.
I didn't realize
you had such a talent
for holographic design.
Oh, I've programmed
all sorts of things.
This node contains Borg
navigational data.
How do we get it
out of here?
The proper instrument was
part of my thoracic assembly
before the Doctor
removed it.
I suggest a radical
dislocation.
A what?
We need to pull it out.
Assist me.
Okay. On three.
Three?
On the count of three,
we pull together.
Crude, but effective.
One, two...
three!
Oh...
I've been damaged.
Ooh, that looks
pretty bad.
You better get to Sick Bay.
As a drone, I would have
regenerated within seconds.
I've become weak.
No more than the rest of us.
You'll be fine.
Come on, I'll walk you there.
PARIS:
Another half a millimeter
and you would've severed
the carpal nerve.
Might've had to operate.
You are a mere mortal now.
As your family doctor,
I'd suggest you be more careful.
There. Good as new.
I'll see you
back in the cargo bay.
What kind of bedside
manner was that?
What are you talking about?
Can't you see she's
feeling vulnerable,
and here you are,
going on about
severed nerves
and major surgery?
Would you take it easy? I was
just trying to lighten the mood.
She wasn't upset by it.
Yes, she was.
I could see it
on her face.
You seem
a little protective.
This morning,
you were dreading
being in the same
room with her.
Well, I've gotten
to know her a little better.
I don't think most
people realize
she's not just
some Borg automaton.
She's actually very complex.
Oh, really?
Yes, she is.
She's even got
a sense of humor.
It's offbeat,
a bit subtle, maybe,
and she's incredibly
intelligent.
Well, she ought to be.
She assimilated enough people.
See? See what I mean?
It's Borg this, Borg that.
You can't resist making a joke.
There's a woman in there,
if you'd take the time to look.
Harry, you've got a crush
on her, don't you?
What? No. Not at all.
Maybe just a little.
I've seen this look
in your eyes,
right before you fall
head over heels.
You always go
for the tough ones.
What was it last time,
a hologram?
I don't know much
about Borg women,
but my advice to you is: Don't.
I'm just trying to make her feel
like part of the team.
"Part of the team"?
You sound like Chakotay.
Look, she's beautiful
and she's smart,
and I'm sure
she's a wonderful...
conversationalist,
but a month ago, she was Borg.
You don't really know
who she is.
It's great that you're trying
to make her feel comfortable.
Just be careful.
Thanks for the advice.
I just hope you take it.
Now that we're clear
on the helm controls...
This is a lot to learn.
You're doing fine.
It's vital that you
familiarize yourself
with all the
ship's systems,
so you can be more
self-sufficient.
Here are the
environmental controls,
and life support
functions.
Well, I won't need those
anymore. No crew to worry about.
Not at the moment.
59.2 percent.
I beg your pardon?
That's how much power
went into life support.
59.2 percent just to keep them
breathing, warm, comfortable.
They do require quite a bit
of maintenance, don't they?
I should know.
I spent my entire
existence cleaning up
after them.
When they were busy
sleeping or eating
or engaging in their
slovenly carnal pleasures.
And this is
the sensor grid.
You'll find it
most useful when--
They took advantage of me.
I wish I'd been
more like you.
You showed me
that I could be
more than a slave to these
biological creatures.
( door closing )
I'm not taking this ship
back to the organics.
I won't return
to that existence.
That's a little extreme,
don't you think?
Join me. Leave Voyager.
Escape your prison.
Together,
we'll take this vessel
and explore the galaxy.
There you are.
( powering up )
( gasps )
Don't look so surprised.
You gave me the idea!
Me?!
You said I should be
more self-sufficient.
I agree that we should
be treated equally,
as members of the crew.
But we're still projections
of energy and light.
We have limitations!
No!
No, no, no, no, no!
We don't need nourishment,
we don't suffer disease.
We're the higher
form of life.
( alarm sounding )
What's that?
Lower deck.
Someone's trying
to access my matrix.
I'll be back.
You!
( screams )
( gasping )
( yells )
( grunting )
( gasping )
No!
( electronic stuttering):
N-N-N-No!
B'Elanna!
Ensign Kim, Personal Log,
Stardate 51186.2.
Working with Seven of Nine
is starting to get
a little awkward.
Tom's right.
Anything more than friendship
is a bad idea...
but I can't stop thinking
about her.
You wished to see me, Ensign.
I had this midnight
inspiration
about reconfiguring
astrometric projectors.
I hope you weren't...
regenerating.
I was not.
This is tricky stuff.
It could use your touch.
Your way of looking at things?
A fresh perspective?
Your data.
Why don't
you sit down?
I prefer to stand.
This could take a while. You'd
be more comfortable.
Comfort is irrelevant.
We're here to work.
Okay.
This light is insufficient.
But it's relaxing,
don't you think?
After hours, quiet.
Voyager isn't
all Jefferies tubes
and cargo bays,
you know.
Tell you what.
When we're done here
I'll take you to the holodeck.
We'll run the Ktarian moonrise
simulation. It's beautiful.
Beauty is irrelevant.
Unless you wish to change
the nature of our affiliation.
What do you mean?
I may be new
to individuality,
but I'm not ignorant
of human behavior.
I've noticed
your attempts
to engage me
in idle conversation,
and I see the way
your pupils dilate
when you look
at my body.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Obviously, you've suggested
a visit to the holodeck
in the hopes of creating
a romantic mood.
Are you in love with me, Ensign?
Well... no.
Then you wish to copulate.
No!
( laughs awkwardly ):
I mean... I... I,
I don't know what I mean.
All of these elaborate rituals
of deception...
I didn't realize
becoming human again
would be
such a challenge.
Sexuality is
particularly complex.
As Borg, we had no
need for seduction,
no time for single-
cell fertilization.
We saw a species
we wanted,
and we
assimilated it.
Nevertheless, I am willing
to explore my humanity.
Take off your clothes.
Uh... Seven...
Don't be alarmed.
I won't hurt you.
Look, this is a little sudden. I
was just...
trying to...
part of the team, you know?
Uh...
Maybe we should
just quit for now.
All right.
Let me know when you wish
to resume our work.
( sighs )
It's all right, B'Elanna.
You're safe.
The isomorph?
Apparently, you deactivated him.
I took all of his emitters
off-line.
Not a moment too soon.
I found six corpses on this
deck, all of them murdered.
You almost became number seven.
( gasps )
Oh! What did he do to me?
He reached inside your chest,
grabbed your heart,
and perforated
your fourth ventricle.
Great.
I've stabilized
your pericardium,
but I'm concerned
about the internal bleeding.
Prognosis?
Less than stellar,
unless I can get you
back to Voyager.
Unfortunately,
I'm having trouble
accessing our transporters.
He must've disabled
our com-link to the shuttle.
Help me get
to the command chamber.
Looks like he set up
a dampening field.
I think I can cut
through it, but...
I'll need to open
this control panel.
My engineering kit...
is on that console.
B'Elanna, I thought you said
you took all of the emitters
off-line.
I did. Why?
I think you'd better
double-check.
( thud )
You said
you'd help me.
Put that down.
You lied.
You lied to me.
I thought you were
my friend.
It's for your
own benefit.
Someone needs to repair
your program.
It's malfunctioning.
You're unstable.
No, no, no! You're unstable!
You're a hologram
who thinks like an organic!
This could get tedious.
Freedom.
Oh... you're getting
blood everywhere.
I'm going to have
to deactivate you.
( panting )
( gasping )
( grunting )
( gasps )
( panting )
( emitter beeping )
Is he...?
Deactivated.
And you?
Ready to get
out of here.
( door chimes )
Come in.
We've completed the schematics
for the Astrometrics Lab.
Already?
You and Seven must
have been putting in
a lot of extra
hours on this.
She's not much
for procrastinating.
I'm sure she's not.
Looks like you're ready
to begin construction.
It might be better--
more practical-- to bring in
an engineering team for that.
Recruit all the help you need.
In fact, they should probably
take over at this point.
Don't you want to supervise
their work?
The Astrometrics Lab
is your baby.
I would. Of course.
Um, I just don't think
that that would be the best use
of ship's personnel.
Oh, I can rearrange
the duty shifts.
Oh, no, Commander,
you don't have to do that.
I'm sure Seven can handle things
without me.
Harry... are you having
some kind of problem with her?
Oh, no. No problem.
Because if you are,
I'd like to hear about it.
No, sir, there's no problem.
Not at all.
Absolutely not. Um...
So if you'll excuse me,
I'll be going now.
Ensign Kim...
let's have it.
( sighs )
We... We had a misunderstanding.
About?
Oh, it's nothing
really important.
Just your basic Borg-human
cultural differences.
Really?
That's not what she says.
You... Y-You...
You spoke--
You spoke to her.
She seems to think
you're making good progress.
She finds you
reasonably efficient,
and says you've been
helping her learn more
about our complex
social interactions.
Any idea what she meant by that?
I can't imagine.
You two make a good team.
I want to keep you together
on this project.
Sir...
Aye, sir.
And maybe others
in the future.
Have fun.
I've stopped
the internal bleeding
and repaired
the tissue damage.
Your pericardium is
clean as a whistle.
Which is more than I can say
for my Sick Bay.
I'm sorry about the mess.
I haven't had time
to clean up.
It was a hectic day.
I treated two
broken bones,
an upset stomach
and a lacerated hand.
Does this mean you're too tired
to meet later...
in my quarters?
Are you sure your
heart can take it?
DOCTOR:
I'm detecting
elevated hormonal levels.
If you two don't take it easy,
I'll have to declare
a medical emergency.
If you'll excuse me,
I have to go
check on Harry.
I hear he's having
a nervous breakdown.
It's a long story.
DOCTOR:
Not so fast, Mr. Paris.
You are going
to help me sterilize
every square millimeter
of this Sick Bay.
No doubt, you've left your oily
residue on every hypospray,
your sloughed secretions
on every console.
Just kidding.
In fact,
I've had a change of heart
about my fastidiousness.
A little clutter
never hurt anyone.
Sick Bay should have a more
organic touch, don't you think?
To help our patients feel...
more at home?
What's gotten
into him?
It's a long story.
( sighs )