JANEWAY:
It's not as difficult
as it looks.
The first rule is:
Don't be afraid
of the clay.
SEVEN:
I fear nothing.
I mean you can't
concern yourself
with making a mistake,
or whether the image
you had in your mind
is what's taking form
in front of you.
You just have
to let your hands--
and the clay--
do the work.
Here.
( horse neighs in distance )
Go ahead.
I think the nose could be
a little stronger.
Well, that's
a start.
Keep going.
( church bell
ringing in distance )
This activity is
truly unproductive.
The end result has no use.
No necessary task
has been accomplished.
Time has been expended,
nothing more.
That depends on how you
look at it, doesn't it?
I find sculpting
helps me unwind, relax.
The concept
of relaxation
is difficult for me
to understand.
As a Borg,
my time was spent
working
at a specific task.
When it was completed,
I was assigned another.
It was efficient.
Well, so is this.
It helps
my own efficiency
to forget about Voyager
for awhile.
I'd be embarrassed
to show Maestro Leonardo
something like this, but...
I get a great deal
of pleasure
in working the clay...
in creating something.
But why here,
in this simulation,
among these
archaic objects
and this disorganized
environment?
Frankly, it's refreshing
to take myself
out of the 24th century
every now and then.
And a little disorganization...
can be very encouraging
to the imagination.
You might want
to try it sometime.
Are you suggesting that I create
one of these holodeck programs?
You might find it interesting.
It's a way of exploring
aspects of yourself
that probably didn't fit
into your life as a Borg--
imagination,
creativity,
fantasy.
I am uncertain why these things
are necessary.
Well, they aren't
necessary, Seven,
but they're an important part
of one's life,
because imagination
frees the mind,
it inspires
ideas and solutions,
and it can provide
a great deal of pleasure.
Human progress,
the human mind itself
couldn't exist
without them.
When I was a child,
I studied these drawings.
I even built some
of these models.
Da Vinci was always
a great inspiration to me.
He was a very busy man.
Oh, yes,
a prolific artist
and a scientist as well.
Far, far ahead of his time.
That design,
for example.
He conceived
of an airplane
centuries before
one was actually built.
Seven?
BORG COLLECTIVE:
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
Your distinctiveness
will be added to our own.
MAN:
Annika!
You will be assimilated.
You will be
assimilated.
( raven shrieks )
Seven, what is it?
I don't know.
( dramatic
theme music playing )
It's happened three times now
in different locations,
at different times of the day.
I experience a series
of disjointed images in my mind.
Can you be
more specific?
Were these
hallucinations?
I don't know.
I've never hallucinated.
It's as if I were aboard
a Borg vessel, but...
but I was frightened.
I felt fear.
Each experience
is similar--
I'm pursued by the Borg.
They want
to assimilate me.
I'm-I'm running
from them, and then...
and then, each time,
I see a bird.
A bird?
Yes, a large, black bird,
flying toward me,
shrieking,
attacking me.
Hm.
Your hippocampus is
in a state of agitation.
What does that mean?
As your human
physiology
continues
to reassert itself,
psychological symptoms
are bound to manifest
in a variety of ways--
through dreams,
hallucinations,
hypnagogic
regression...
Hypnagogic
regression?
Flashbacks.
You could be experiencing
some sort of
post-traumatic
stress disorder.
That makes sense.
You were assimilated
by the Borg.
You've gone through
an intense, prolonged trauma.
I was not
traumatized.
I was raised
by the Borg.
I don't see them
as threatening.
Why would I
experience fear?
I don't know.
Will I keep having
these flashbacks?
I'll need to study
your neural scans further.
In the meantime,
your digestive system
is fully functional.
Now is as good a time as any
for you to begin taking
solid and liquid nutrients.
Oral consumption
is inefficient.
And unnecessary, if you're lucky
enough to be a hologram.
But your human
physiology requires it.
I'll draw up a list
of nutritional requirements.
Take it to Mr. Neelix
in the Mess Hall.
I hesitate to inflict
his cooking on you,
but it'll have to do.
I do not enjoy
this sensation.
Something
is happening to me
and I don't
know what it is.
It's as though
I'm being driven somehow.
Chakotay to the Captain.
Go ahead.
Our guests have arrived.
They're being escorted
to the briefing room.
On my way.
Representatives
of the B'omar.
I've been trying to negotiate
passage through their space,
but so far, they've been
difficult to deal with.
I hope they've had
a change of heart.
I'll stay here and wait
for the Doctor's instructions.
( sighs )
We'll help you
through this, Seven.
You'll be all right.
JANEWAY: Have you had a chance
to consider our request?
Congratulations,
Captain.
Against our better judgment,
the B'omar Sovereignty
has agreed to grant
your vessel passage
through
our territory.
On behalf of my crew,
thank you.
That will cut three months
off our journey.
However,
there are a few stipulations--
guidelines
that you must adhere to.
You'll have
our complete cooperation.
We expect
nothing less.
While in our space,
your vessel will
not exceed warp 3
and your weapon systems
will remain off-line.
You will avoid
unnecessary scans
and you will not conduct
surveys of any kind.
You will make no attempt
to explore our space,
and you will avoid
all communications
with nonmilitary craft.
We've also
plotted the course
your vessel
is to follow.
( scoffs )
It'll take us weeks
to follow that course.
If not months.
We've designed
this course
so that your ship would avoid
our populated systems
and industrial areas.
Deviation is not recommended.
There are a total
of 17 checkpoints
where you will submit
your vessel for inspection.
JANEWAY:
Chancellor Gauman,
if I may interrupt.
I appreciate your efforts
in plotting this flight plan,
but, if we could,
I'd like
to negotiate a course
that's a little more...
direct.
Well, what
an unexpected pleasure.
Welcome to the Mess Hall.
Would you like me
to show you around?
My physiology has
reasserted the need
to process
solid nutrients.
The Doctor has
prepared a list
of dietary
requirements.
You will provide
them for me.
Let's see
what we have here.
250 grams glycoproteins,
consisting of
53 percent polypeptides
and 26 percent
fibrous glycogen...
Ugh.
Doesn't sound
very appetizing.
However, a plate
of my chadre kab
should satisfy most
of these essentials,
while providing a pleasurable
culinary experience
at the same time.
Pleasure is irrelevant.
Well, I beg to differ.
A good meal involves much
more than simply providing
the proper nutrients.
Why is that?
Uh, well, it's a...
There's a certain
satisfaction
that comes
from eating food
that's been
carefully prepared.
I'm sure once you try it,
you'll understand.
Now, how would you
like your chadre kab?
Boiled? Baked?
Stir-fried?
Preparation is irrelevant.
Is irrelevant-- maybe.
Maybe not.
This is the first time
ingesting food for you
for quite awhile.
We'll go a little
easy on your stomach.
Steamed.
Yes...
This, uh... This recipe
has been in my family
for generations.
It's considered a delicacy
among my people.
You are Talaxian.
Guilty as charged.
Species 218.
Well, I suppose so.
Your biological
and technological
distinctiveness
was added to our own.
I hadn't realized that.
A small freighter,
containing a crew of 39,
taken in the Dalmine Sector.
They were easily assimilated.
Their dense musculature
made them
excellent drones.
Well, lucky for you,
I guess.
Your nutrients.
Follow me.
Please.
Please what?
It's customary to sit
while eating.
Uh, is something
wrong?
I am unaccustomed
to this.
Borg do not sit.
Well, this is a day of
firsts, then, isn't it?
Now...
Take a bite.
Uh... try that one.
Just kind of, uh...
scoop some up.
That's the way.
Right into your mouth,
just like a
little scout ship
flying into
a shuttle bay.
Take it out.
Keep your mouth closed.
That's right.
Now, you chew--
chew, chew, chew,
chew, chew.
And swallow.
Uh, swallow. Uh...
( swallows )
Curious sensation.
You'll get used to it.
Have some more.
May I bring you
something else?
A soothing cup of tea,
perhaps?
( shrieking )
( gasps )
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
( grunts )
CREWMAN:
Did you see that?
CHAKOTAY:
What about this course?
It's a marginal
adjustment.
The nearest
populated system
is more than three
light-years away.
Definitely not.
You'd pass
directly through
the Agrat-Mot Nebula,
a key resource
in our trade negotiations
with the Nassordin.
I could chart the nebula,
try to avoid...
No, no.
Are your translators
malfunctioning?
TUVOK:
Captain Janeway to the Bridge.
If you'll excuse me.
( alarm beeping )
Report.
I've received
an alert from Security.
Seven of Nine attacked
Neelix in the Mess Hall,
and three other crewmen
on Deck 2.
Janeway to Seven of Nine.
Seven, if you can hear me,
respond.
What's her location?
Deck 6,
Section 28-Alpha.
Take a security team.
GAUMAN:
Captain... what is happening
here?
I wish I knew,
Chancellor.
Chakotay, seal off Deck 6.
BORG COLLECTIVE:
Seven of Nine.
( many indistinct
voices overlapping )
MALE CREWMAN:
Security to Captain Janeway.
We've just seen Seven of Nine.
Her Borg shields
are fully operational
and they've adapted
to our phasers.
Acknowledged.
Bridge to all
security personnel.
Configure your weapons
to a rotating modulation,
but keep them on "stun."
Borg?
You have Borg on your ship?
It's not what
you think.
She is a member of my crew.
We liberated her
from the collective.
She's no longer a Borg.
Then why is she equipped
with Borg shields?
I don't know.
She's able to cross
through the security fields.
She's entering
the armory on Deck 6.
Deck 10.
She's in a turbolift.
Cut power to the turboshafts.
She's blocking
my commands
with a Borg encryption code.
Janeway to Tuvok.
Seven's apparently
headed for Deck 10.
Can you get there
before she does?
I'm moving
into position now, Captain.
We'll take
position here.
( turbolift arriving )
TUVOK:
Lower your weapon,
and stand down.
Fire.
( grunts )
Tuvok to Bridge.
We were unsuccessful.
I have wounded.
She's moving toward
Junction 32-Alpha.
The Shuttle Bay.
I'm erecting a force field.
Harry, reroute all
available power to Deck 10.
Done.
She's accessing
transporter control.
She used
a site-to-site transport.
She's in a shuttlecraft...
powering engines.
Seal the launch doors.
Tractor beam.
No effect.
She's remodulated
the shuttle's shield harmonics.
KIM:
Captain...
Seven's headed directly
into B'omar space.
She's gone
to warp.
She's masked the
shuttle's ion trail.
I've lost her signal.
She's gone.
We'll do everything in our power
to find her,
but we will need permission
to enter B'omar space
to track her shuttle
effectively.
Let's tally
the events, shall we?
First, you arrive
uninvited and unwelcome,
requesting a shortcut
through our space.
Then you proceed to unleash
some sort of rogue Borg,
and now you want
us to help you get it back.
I apologize
for what's happened here,
but we certainly didn't
"unleash" anyone.
We can resolve this
situation quickly, gentlemen,
if we work together.
Captain Janeway,
after what I've seen here,
I question
your competence.
May I remind you that
you're still on my ship--
And you are only one vessel
among many of ours.
Your Borg will be dealt with
quickly and efficiently.
It's being tracked
as we speak.
Tracked... how?
Every vessel, every object,
every particle of dust
that crosses our borders
is immediately identified
and traced
by our perimeter grid.
The Borg will be found...
and destroyed.
Chancellor...
There will be no sharing
of information.
From this point on, your vessel
will maintain a distance
of at least five light-years
from our borders.
Any deviation
will be considered
an act of aggression.
Commander,
escort our guests
to the transporter room.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I've assembled a team
to analyze every square meter
of the cargo bay.
This has essentially been
her quarters
for the past two months.
I'm determined
to find something here
that might shed some light
on Seven of Nine's actions.
( tricorder beeping softly )
You're taking this kind
of hard, aren't you?
What's that
supposed to mean?
We had a working
relationship.
Well, what's that
supposed to mean?
It's not what
you're thinking.
What am I
thinking, Harry?
Never mind.
( beeping intensifies )
Take a look at this.
Anything?
It's a Borg
data-link.
It contains a succession
of log entries
written in Borg
alphanumeric code.
I'm getting pretty good
with the Borg language.
I think I can
translate them.
Get on it.
It seems we've made quite
an impression on the B'omar.
In the last hour, they've
doubled the number of ships
patrolling
their borders,
and they've increased
the sensitivity
of the perimeter
grid by 36 percent.
So much for diplomacy.
The Doctor analyzed
the data
from Seven of Nine's
last transport.
He's found something
he wants us to see.
Maybe this was
inevitable.
Even if Seven did want
to stay on Voyager,
her Borg nature
may have won out.
We can remove implant
after implant,
but maybe
at her core,
she'll always be part
of the collective.
No. I won't
accept that.
Deck 5.
She was responding to us--
interacting with people
outside of the collective
for the first time.
She was adapting
to this environment
and to this crew.
But where is she going?
We've scanned space
for a distance
of 40 light-years.
We've found no evidence
of Borg ships,
so she can't be trying
to rejoin the collective.
She may plan to take the
shuttle back to Borg space.
10,000 light-years from here?
I don't think so. No.
Something else
is going on.
We're missing a piece
of the puzzle.
In the meantime,
the B'omar intend to find her,
and if they do,
she'll probably resist them.
One more reason
for us to find her first.
What have you found,
Doctor?
Something
most peculiar.
This graphic represents
the matter conversion data
from Seven of Nine's
last transport.
If you'll notice,
there's a high concentration
of Borg organelles in the bone
marrow and lymphatic tissue.
The dormant nanoprobes
in Seven of Nine's cells
have reasserted themselves--
taken over blood
cell production,
and they're growing
new Borg implants.
13 percent
of the Borg technology
I removed three weeks ago
has regenerated
in a matter of hours.
You said the nanoprobes in
her bloodstream were dormant.
What reactivated them?
I don't know.
But I've developed a way
to stop the process.
This hypospray contains
a genetic resequencing vector.
It should neutralize
the nanoprobes.
That means someone needs
to get close enough to do it.
Report.
We've analyzed
the B'omar perimeter grid.
It's sophisticated,
but not without
its vulnerabilities.
It might be possible
to penetrate the grid
by recalibrating our shields
to match its frequency.
The trick is going to be
our energy signature.
Voyager's too big to hide,
but a shuttlecraft with
the proper shield modulation
and its engines powered down
could drift right through
without so much as a peep.
Nice work, gentlemen.
Proceed.
The Doctor's genetic
resequencer
should keep her sedated
until you get back to the ship.
Once you've penetrated
the perimeter,
there will be no further
communication
with Voyager.
You'll be on your own.
Captain, it is possible
that Seven will adapt
to the resequencer.
I know.
If it fails,
and you're unable
to reason with her...
you have my authorization
to stop her...
with any force necessary.
Understood.
BORG COLLECTIVE:
Seven of Nine,
grid nine-two
of subjunction 12.
( raven shrieking in distance )
You will be assimilated.
( console beeping )
B'OMAR:
Borg drone, you have committed
an infraction
against the B'omar Sovereignty.
Cut power to your engines
and lower your shields.
Prepare to be boarded.
( alarm blaring )
You will proceed no further.
We will not...
I'm detecting weapon
signatures...
Federation and B'omar.
Five B'omar vessels
are adrift, heavily damaged.
Life signs are stable.
I've located
Seven's shuttle.
It's 2.5 million
kilometers from here.
Adjust course
to intercept.
The implants in Seven's body
are disrupting
the transporter signal.
I can't get a lock.
See if you can remodulate
our transporters
to match her shields.
You want to beam
in there?
Yes.
I don't think
that's such a good idea, Tuvok.
Close quarters,
Borg against Vulcan?
No offense, but you
don't stand a chance
if she decides
to put up a fight.
It's my hope
that the element of surprise
will work in my favor.
Do you have a better idea?
Come to think of it, no.
( alarm beeps )
She's charging weapons.
Set my coordinates
for the aft compartment.
Ready.
Energize.
Come on, Tuvok.
Give me a sign.
COMPUTER: Warning. Propulsion
systems are off-line.
Damn!
That's a level-5
force field, Lieutenant.
I suggest you be
more careful.
Why have you
left Voyager?
I am Borg.
You were Borg...
but you're human now.
You are part
of our crew.
For a brief time,
I was human.
But I have come to realize
that I am Borg.
I will always be Borg.
What prompted this realization?
Every Borg ship is coded to emit
a distinct resonance frequency
to guide drones who have become
separated from the collective.
A homing beacon.
Yes.
I am following a signal.
A Borg vessel is waiting for me.
We've scanned
this entire region for Borg.
There are none.
You're wrong.
They are here.
Vulcan.
Species 3259.
Your enlarged neocortex
produces superior
analytical abilities.
Your distinctiveness
will be added to our...
Seven?
No.
I will not assimilate you.
Once I have returned
to the collective,
you will go back to Voyager
and tell Captain Janeway
what's happened to me.
Thank her for her patience...
for her kindness.
Curious.
Your behavior
demonstrates
affection
and sentiment.
Traits of humanity.
Hardly Borg.
You have been
experiencing
hallucinations,
flashbacks?
Yes.
Does that usually occur
when a resonance signal
is activated?
No.
COLLECTIVE:
Seven of Nine,
grid nine-two
of subjunction 12.
But I can hear them...
calling me.
I'm frightened.
That's understandable.
Lower the force field.
We can return
to Voyager
and find out what's
happening to you.
I am your shipmate.
We can return to Voyager
together.
I must rejoin the collective.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
I've been trying to retrace
Seven of Nine's footsteps--
her actions
during the last few days--
but I'm still no closer
to understanding
what's happened.
Captain?
Am I disturbing you?
Not at all, Harry.
I've managed to decipher
Seven's log entries.
And...?
There's nothing
that indicates
she was planning
to leave the ship.
The entries are
pretty unremarkable.
She describes
her daily routines,
the number of hours
spent regenerating,
that sort of thing.
There were some
personal log entries,
mostly observations
about the crew's behavior.
I'm mentioned
in quite a few of them.
Apparently, she finds
my behavior easy to predict,
whatever that means.
Don't take it personally.
Coming from Seven,
that's probably a compliment.
( chuckles )
Uh, the most recent entries
are kind of strange.
Descriptions of
bizarre images,
almost like a record
of her dreams.
The hallucinations?
Maybe so.
Sometimes she's
in a Borg vessel
running... or hiding
behind a bulkhead,
falling down a shaft.
Borg everywhere,
chasing her.
Nightmarish stuff.
What about this... bird?
She mentions it
several times.
It flies at her,
shrieking.
I don't know
what it means.
"The feathers are black.
"Wingspan approximately
one half meter.
"The eyes are yellow
"and it has a powerful
triangular beak.
"When it looks at me...
"I am paralyzed.
"I cannot move.
"It seems to know me,
"but I don't understand
how that's possible.
"It's merely a bird,
an inferior form of life,
but the sight of it
fills me with fear."
It sounds like she's describing
a member of the...
Corvidae family,
like a crow or...
( whispers )
Or a raven.
She's describing a raven.
Why is that important?
Because now I know
what to look for.
Chakotay, calibrate
our long-range sensors
to scan for
any Federation signature
other than
our two shuttlecraft.
Captain?
Do it.
Bring the ship about, Ensign,
and lay in a course
for B'omar space.
Aye, Captain.
The resonance signal is coming
from the lunar surface.
The Borg are waiting
for me there.
I don't know
why I'm frightened.
They are my people.
If you are afraid,
then leave this place.
Once I have been reintegrated
into the collective,
my fears will disappear.
Deactivate the force field.
I will accompany you
to the surface.
You don't need
to go alone.
You would be assimilated.
I don't believe so.
I think the situation
is not what it appears.
What do you mean?
What else could it be?
I am uncertain,
but I am willing
to go with you to the surface
to find out.
JANEWAY:
Voyager to Paris.
Paris here, Captain.
Glad to hear your voice.
Tuvok is with Seven of Nine.
I haven't been able to establish
communication with him
since he transported
to her shuttle.
I've tracked them
to an M-Class moon
orbiting the fifth planet
of a yellow dwarf star.
I'm picking up
an unusual resonance signal
from the surface--
it's erratic.
I haven't been able
to identify it.
Acknowledged.
We've detected
several B'omar ships
closing in on your position.
What's your condition?
Warp engines are off-line.
Shields are
at 50 percent.
JANEWAY:
Try to locate them, Tom.
We're on our way.
( tricorder beeping )
The signal's
getting stronger.
They're here.
I'm sure of it.
This way.
If you wish, we can return
to the shuttle.
No. I have
to find out.
What is it?
TUVOK: It's a Federation
vessel,
partially assimilated
by the Borg.
There are
no life signs.
Tritanium decay
suggests
it has been here
for nearly 20 years.
This vessel is familiar.
( repetitive buzzing beeps )
This is the signal
that's drawn me here.
( beeps stop )
Annika!
WOMAN:
Run, Annika!
Run! Hide!
Papa?
Help me.
( gasps, then whimpers )
No! No!
Seven, I'm here.
Listen to me.
Come.
It happened here.
This is where it began.
This is where
I was assimilated.
( sighs )
This was our ship.
We lived here.
We lived here for a long time.
My father did experiments.
They were very important
and we had to travel
a long way.
I had my birthday here.
My cake had
six candles on it and...
and one more to grow on.
And then the men came.
Papa tried to fight them,
but they were too strong.
I tried to hide.
Maybe they wouldn't find me
because I was little.
But they did.
And then Papa said
we were going to crash
and... the big man
picked me up...
and then suddenly,
we weren't on this ship anymore.
We were somewhere else.
And then I became Borg.
Fascinating.
This resonance signal
must have been active
since the ship
was assimilated
and Voyager passed
within range.
The ship is under attack.
The B'omar.
The ship will collapse.
We must get out of here.
The B'omar still
aren't responding to our hails.
CHAKOTAY:
Standing by to fire.
Target their weapon systems.
Tom, what's your status?
I've located Tuvok and Seven,
but there's a lot
of interference.
I'm attempting
to lock onto them now, Captain.
This way!
( grunts )
Are you all right?
I am undamaged.
This was the only
way to the hatch.
Perhaps there is
another way out.
There's a hull rupture
in the forward compartment.
It may provide
a means of escape.
Start digging.
Quickly!
We've disabled
two of their ships.
The third is still
firing at the surface.
We're being hailed,
audio only.
GAUMAN: You're committing
an act of war, Captain.
You've left me no choice,
Councilor.
Reinforcements are arriving.
You will be destroyed...
I don't have time for this.
Target their weapons array.
Seven,
I need your help!
PARIS:
I've got them, Captain.
We're on our way back
to Voyager.
Acknowledged. Good work.
I'm detecting a fleet
of B'omar vessels approaching.
68 ships.
Ensign, as soon as
Mr. Paris's shuttle has docked,
take us out of B'omar space.
Warp 8.
ENSIGN: Aye, sir.
Looks like there won't be
any shortcuts this time.
There you are.
I wanted to tell you
that the Doctor said
he could adjust
one of your implants
so that you won't receive
any more homing signals.
Thank you.
I hope you don't mind
that I activated
this program.
Not at all.
I've been thinking
about what you said...
that this was a place
to encourage your imagination.
Is that appealing
to you?
I'm not certain.
I find myself...
constructing scenarios,
considering alternative
possibilities.
What if my parents and I
had not encountered the Borg?
What would our lives
have been?
I would have been raised
by them, learned from them.
They would have influenced
what I became--
who and what I am.
And you...
would have done
the same for them.
If you'd like to know
more about your parents,
there's information
in the Federation database.
Information?
It seems they were
fairly well-known.
For being unconventional,
and for some rather unique
scientific theories.
You might like to read
what's there.
It might...
encourage
your imagination.
Perhaps I will.
Someday.
Good night, Captain.
( holodeck door opens, closes )
( dramatic
theme music playing )