( dramatic theme playing )
Sorry.
I didn't realize
that you'd been
assigned here today.
I wasn't.
This space was unoccupied,
so I came here to work.
On what?
I'm reconfiguring
the power couplings
in this section.
Why?
The Astrometrics Lab
requires additional energy.
I see.
So you're rerouting power
from other locations
like... Engineering.
They are minor adjustments.
Primary systems
will not be affected.
Unless, of course,
someone is trying
to do a warp core
diagnostic,
which my crew has been
trying to do all morning.
We have lost hours of work
because of this.
There is no need
for anger.
I had no intention
of causing a problem.
What, "sorry" isn't in
the Borg vocabulary?
You need to
check with me
before you touch
the power systems.
Understood?
Understood.
I am unaccustomed
to working in a hierarchy.
In the collective,
there was no need
to ask permission.
If you're going to be
a member of this crew,
get used to it.
( beeping )
Procedures exist
for a reason.
We've got
to work together.
We follow
the same set of rules--
Lieutenant?
I was given
that lecture once,
by Captain Janeway
when I first joined
this crew.
If I could adjust
to Starfleet life...
...so can you.
Of course.
I am...
sorry for the inconvenience.
Doc, I've got to go
run a few errands.
I'll be back soon.
Not so fast, Mr. Paris.
Can't these errands wait
until the end
of your duty shift?
Uh... Well, it's my
Conn report, actually.
I just realized
I forgot to turn it in,
and Chakotay gives me
a hard time when it's late.
You've been here
all afternoon.
Didn't this occur
to you before?
Well, we've been
so...busy
that I guess it just
slipped my mind.
I see.
Well, since
it's an emergency,
don't let me
stand in your way.
Thanks.
Hmm.
Sir.
( console beeping )
Computer, lock on
to these coordinates.
I need
a site-to-site transport.
No, wait.
Access the central
replicator files first.
Ah...
perfect.
( sighs )
( beeping )
( whoosh )
Are those supposed
to make up
for canceling on me
last night?
I got stuck with an extra shift
on the Bridge.
What could I say--
"Sorry, Captain, I've got
a date with B'Elanna"?
And what about
right now?
Aren't you supposed
to be working in Sickbay?
I said I had to go
deliver a Conn report.
Not bad.
But he'll be
expecting you back.
He can wait.
( dramatic theme playing )
( gasps )
What is it?
I just had the feeling that
somebody was watching us.
I must be completely
paranoid
about getting caught in a
compromising position, heh.
Kind of exciting,
isn't it?
( triumphant theme playing )
Your trapezius
is hard as a rock.
You haven't been following
the relaxation regimen
I prescribed for you.
I've been too busy.
The usual story.
Have you been getting
enough sleep?
More or less.
Mostly less.
Mm-hmm. And have
your headaches
been getting any worse?
No, but they're not getting
any better either.
They're like hot needles
driving into my skull.
These symptoms are
hardly surprising, Captain.
You work absurdly
long hours
under constant stress,
eating on the run,
without sufficient
exercise or rest.
Your body is crying out
for mercy.
It certainly is right now.
( spine pops, Janeway gasping )
There must be some easier
way to do this, doctor.
A hypospray, maybe?
Always looking for
the simple fix.
Sometimes there's
no substitute for
intensive osteopathic
pressure therapy.
You're fortunate
to have a masseur
who can work all day
without tiring.
( com chirps )
CHAKOTAY: Bridge to the Captain.
Commander, unless
this is an emergency,
my patient
is unavailable.
I'm here, Chakotay.
What is it?
CHAKOTAY:
We've reached the source of
those energy readings,
and I thought you'd like to see
what we've found.
On my way.
Captain!
I know what
you're going to say, doctor,
but I can't neglect
my responsibilities.
Actually, I was going to
suggest a change of outfit.
CHAKOTAY:
Binary pulsars.
The gravitational forces
between them are so intense
that everything within
50 million kilometers
is getting pulled in.
Don't worry.
We're well out of range.
Gamma radiation
levels are high,
but as long
as we're careful,
I think we can collect
some invaluable data.
Captain,
am I boring you?
I'm sorry.
I guess I'm a little
too tired to concentrate
on stellar phenomena
right now.
I'll leave this project
in your capable hands, hmm?
( people chatting indistinctly )
You wanted to see me,
Lieutenant?
Yes. I'm trying
to increase
the efficiency of
the impulse drive,
but I wanted to make sure
that I wasn't compromising
helm control.
Sensible precaution.
I'd be glad to help.
Good. All of the specs
are at my upper
workstation.
Then let's get started.
( console beeping repetitively )
( beeping stops )
Did you hear something?
You always think
you hear something.
( turbolift arriving )
Commander.
Lieutenant.
Here is the power usage data
you requested.
Right. Of course.
I didn't expect it
quite so...promptly.
Which I guess I should have,
uh, coming from you.
I mean, I'm grateful
that you got the data
to me so quickly. Thanks.
( console beeping )
( both sigh )
( dramatic theme playing )
Tuvok.
( nervous chuckle )
Tuvok, I guess that was
kind of embarrassing.
I don't experience
embarrassment.
Right.
Well, then I guess
there's no harm done.
It's not like there was
a security violation
or anything.
None that
I am aware of.
So I guess
there's nothing
that would have to go on
any kind of report.
You want me to conceal
what I've observed
of your relationship
with Lieutenant Torres.
Well, I'd certainly
never ask you
to be dishonest.
Certainly not.
B'ELANNA:
Do you think he'll say
anything to the Captain?
I don't know.
Well, how did he sound?
Annoyed? Amused?
He sounded Vulcan.
What more can I tell you?
Deck 1.
( beeps )
We have got to be more
careful with appearances.
We shouldn't go into
the briefing at the same time.
Good idea.
Okay, you go in first.
I'll come in a minute later.
No. That'll look
even more suspicious.
Listen to us.
We're acting like criminals
when we haven't done
anything wrong.
Well, I'm not saying
that we have.
I just thought we wanted
to keep this relationship
to ourselves.
We do, right?
Do you?
If you do.
Computer, halt turbolift.
Let's figure out how
we're going to handle this.
( sighs )
Well...
I don't think that it's
anybody else's business
how we feel about each other.
Neither do I.
Right, then we're agreed.
We're just a little
more careful in public,
and we don't say
anything to anybody.
At least for now.
Now?
Sounds like you see
a future in this.
( chuckles )
I would never
be so presumptuous.
Smooth recovery,
Lieutenant.
I thought so.
Computer, resume.
So I'll go first,
and you follow.
Right.
( door opens )
Here's the plan.
We'll circle the two pulsars
at a minimum distance
of 80 million kilometers.
That might not be
far enough.
We've been detecting
some random proton bursts.
A strong one could
knock out our shields.
Tom, go to 90.
Keep it a safe distance.
Yes, sir.
CHAKOTAY: Tuvok,
keep our shields
at maximum strength.
Divert auxiliary power
if you need it.
I want to take every precaution
on this survey.
Report any problems immediately,
no matter how small.
JANEWAY: Dismissed.
Lieutenants
Paris and Torres,
I'd like to speak
with you for a moment.
Thanks.
JANEWAY:
I don't usually
pry into the personal lives
of my crew, but in this case,
I have to question
your recent conduct.
I guess Tuvok...
JANEWAY: Tuvok?
I haven't heard a word
from Tuvok.
But you two have been making
enough of a public display
that half the ship
is gossiping about it.
Believe me,
that wasn't our intention--
JANEWAY:
You are senior officers,
and I expect you
to maintain the standard
for the rest of the crew.
But this adolescent behavior
makes me question my faith
in you both.
If you choose to
pursue a relationship,
that's your business.
But you consider yourselves
under orders
to use better judgment
about it.
Is that understood?
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, Captain.
Dismissed.
( dramatic theme playing )
( sighs )
( beeping )
Computer, hot coffee, black.
( gasping )
DOCTOR:
Commander Chakotay is suffering
bone decalcification,
tissue necrosis,
decreased visual acuity--
All classic signs of aging.
But they've developed
within hours.
Any theories?
There's a rare genetic
disorder called progeria,
which causes children
to age prematurely.
But there's never
been an adult case,
and it was supposedly
eradicated two centuries ago.
Even so, I took a close look
at your DNA.
These segments regulate
your body's metabolism.
My scans indicate that they've
been hyper-stimulated somehow.
What's the prognosis?
I can't speculate on that
until I've identified the cause.
There's no sign of
an infectious agent.
We spent several hours
near a binary pulsar
that was emitting
intense gamma radiation.
Our shields were operating.
I don't see how I could
have been exposed to it.
At this point,
we can't rule out anything.
I'm going to take a closer look
at the data we collected.
We should also run
scans of my quarters,
as well as my office
and the Bridge--
Everywhere I've been today.
I'm not prepared
to send you back
on duty yet, Commander.
I may look pretty strange,
but my mind
is perfectly clear.
I'd rather stay busy
than just sit here.
I have no idea how
your symptoms will progress.
You should remain
in Sickbay for observation.
He's right, Chakotay.
I'll keep you informed.
Whatever's affecting
the Commander's DNA
is working at
a submolecular level.
I'd like to set up
an electron resonance scanner
in the Science Lab
to get a closer look.
Use whatever you need.
And ask B'Elanna
to give you a hand.
Still having headaches,
Captain?
I don't need any more lectures
about working too hard, doctor.
Chakotay's the one who needs
your attention right now.
I'll get to work on
the scanner right away.
( door opens )
"Under orders
to use better judgment"?
Well, that's pretty harsh.
I hope
I can manage it.
Well, she does
have a point.
You could have been
more discreet.
Oh. I forgot
I was talking to
the most upstanding Ensign
in Starfleet.
Good morning.
Neelix.
I was just about to whip up
a fresh batch
of scrambled eggs.
Would you like some?
KIM: Actually,
I was hoping
you might have
some leftover
pleekarind casserole
from last night.
For breakfast?
I like it, heh.
I'm sure I can find
some for you.
So I guess
your relationship
isn't exactly
a secret anymore.
Do you think anybody
on this ship
can keep a secret?
( clattering crash )
( dramatic theme playing )
PARIS:
Neelix!
( gasping )
Aah-- Aah-- What's--
What's happening?
Paris to the doctor.
I'm bringing Neelix
to Sickbay.
It's an emergency.
DOCTOR:
Now pay attention, Mr. Paris.
These scans should indicate
whether...
Hmm.
What is it?
It seems that your DNA
has been hyper-stimulated,
just like
Commander Chakotay's.
But Neelix doesn't
seem to be aging.
No. The effects
are quite different.
If anything, I look...
like a Mylean.
They occupy a region of space
near Talax.
Interesting.
Do Talaxians and Myleans
share a common ancestry?
Not that I know of.
Do the two races ever
intermarry?
Yes. As a matter of fact,
my great-grandfather
was Mylean.
Then one-eighth
of your genetic material
was inherited from him.
Those must be the genes
which have become stimulated.
Too bad my great-grandfather
wasn't a little better-looking.
Hmm. As far as I can tell,
his condition seems stable.
I'm going to leave you
in charge of Sickbay
so I can continue
the DNA analysis.
If anyone else
comes in,
I'll run
a cellular scan.
Is there anything else
I can do?
Do your best
to keep them comfortable.
Until we have
more information,
that's the best
either of us can do.
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunting )
Thought you
might be thirsty.
Thanks.
Do you smell
something strange?
I... I'm...
I'm afraid that's me.
I seem to be developing
Mylean sweat glands.
Sorry.
It's not so bad.
Well, whatever happens,
I... I try to keep in mind
that things could be worse.
( grunting )
I still have my home
here on Voyager,
my friends...
Your hair.
True,
but I'd gladly lose it
if I could have
my taste buds back.
At least you're not
losing your eyesight.
See that display
over there?
It's nothing but a blur.
You think that's bad?
The doctor tells me my pupils
have dilated 60 percent.
I can't even look at that
display, it's so bright.
Yeah? Well, I've got
chronic arthritis in my fingers.
I can barely
keep this glass steady.
That's nothing.
My spinal column
is fusing together.
In a matter of days,
I won't be able to walk.
Got you beat.
I can barely walk now.
( door opens )
( groans )
NEELIX: Lieutenant, can we help?
I don't think so.
I'm releasing you both
back to your quarters.
I've just gotten reports
of more patients
on the way.
It's going
to get crowded in here.
How's the scanner?
B'ELANNA: Almost ready.
Good.
This disorder seems
to be spreading rapidly
among the crew.
Does that mean
we'll all be affected?
Right now, it only means
that we need
to find some answers
as quickly as possible.
All right.
Give the scanner a try.
I'll start with
Commander Chakotay.
( beeping )
How's the resolution?
Very nice.
Now, let's focus in on
the hyper-stimulated
segments of his DNA.
Can you give me
more magnification?
Coming up.
DOCTOR:
That's odd.
What is?
There seems to be
some kind of contaminant
on the base pair
sequence.
It didn't show up
on the first scan.
I need a closer look.
I'm going to maximum
magnification.
( dramatic theme playing )
What do you see?
I'm not exactly sure.
Well, what does it look like?
See for yourself.
I'm no microbiologist, but...
that doesn't look
like it belongs there.
Believe me, it doesn't.
I've never seen
anything like it.
This level
of submolecular technology
is well beyond anything
Starfleet has developed.
What are those markings?
Some kind of alien writing?
I wish I knew.
They might help us determine
where it came from.
But who could have put this
into Chakotay's cells
without his knowledge?
Let me try
a compositional analysis.
( beeping )
( dramatic theme
turns suspenseful )
It's in Mr. Neelix's DNA
as well.
Is this what's causing
the mutations?
A good scientist never jumps
to conclusions, Lieutenant,
but I'd say
it's a distinct possibility.
I'm having trouble getting a
clear reading from this sample.
It looks almost like the, um...
whatever it is
could be slightly out of phase.
That must be why my initial
scans didn't reveal it.
I'm compensating
for the phase variance.
You're not gonna believe this,
but I'm picking up
an energy signature.
This thing is transmitting
some kind of a signal.
To where?
I don't know.
It's too weak
to travel very far.
Access the internal sensors
and set them
to a phase variance of .15.
Right.
Lieutenant.
Your program is being deleted.
DOCTOR: How?
I don't know.
I'm transferring you
back to Sickbay.
( gasping )
( groaning )
B'Elanna...
Science Lab
to the Bridge.
This is the doctor.
PARIS:
In the last hour,
three more patients
have come in
with genetic mutations.
The effects are starting
to become life-threatening.
What happened to
B'Elanna?
The alveoli
in her lungs
suddenly stopped
processing oxygen.
I've got her on
respiratory support.
She almost died.
What about
the doctor?
The computer logs
in the Science Lab
show that he was trying to
transfer himself to Sickbay.
Something must
have gone wrong
while he was
in transit.
PARIS:
Could the doctor's
program...?
DOCTOR:
Seven of Nine,
this is the doctor.
Can you hear me?
It's me, the doctor.
I've tapped
into your audio implants
so only you can hear me.
It's imperative
that you tell no one.
Make any excuse
to get out of there
and report to Holodeck 2.
I'm hiding
in the da Vinci simulation.
I'll explain everything
when you get here.
KIM:
Seven was checking that.
JANEWAY:
Seven?
About the doctor's
research.
Yes. I examined
their work area.
There was no record
of any findings.
The electron resonance scanner
appeared to be malfunctioning.
I...could return
to the Science Lab
and attempt
to repair it.
Keep me informed.
DOCTOR:
Hold your head
this way, Carlotta.
I can only conclude
that someone has implanted
these microscopic tags
in the DNA of the crew
to cause genetic mutations.
For what purpose?
I don't know,
and I get the feeling
they don't want us
to find out.
Explain.
When Lieutenant Torres
and I started making progress
in our investigation,
we were both incapacitated.
Call me paranoid,
but I don't think
that is a coincidence.
If you're correct,
perhaps our actions
are being monitored.
That's why I couldn't risk
contacting anyone
over the com system.
Our first
course of action
should be to collect
more information.
My thinking exactly.
B'Elanna wanted to adjust
the ship's internal sensors
to a phase variance of .15.
I'd like to do the same
to your Borg sensory nodes.
Proceed.
( beeping )
Computer, give me
a type-4 micro-inducer.
Hmm.
( whirring )
Now, take a look around,
and tell me what you see.
Do you see
anything...
unusual?
Energy signatures...
or perhaps something
that might be
transmitting a signal?
No.
That's one room down,
256 to go.
I suggest
a deck-by-deck survey.
If you need to contact me,
use com frequency Epsilon 2.
I've isolated it
from the rest of the system.
Understood.
And be careful.
Someone out there
could be watching.
( sighing softly )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( beeps )
( door opens )
Deck 5.
( beeping )
( indistinct chatter )
( com chirps )
Computer, frequency Epsilon 2.
Doctor, the aliens
are here on the ship.
I can see them everywhere.
DOCTOR:
This is worse than I imagined.
You've got
to let the Captain know.
( beeping )
( door chimes )
Yes? Yes!
Good morning,
Captain.
That's a matter of opinion.
What is it?
Internal scans
haven't revealed anything
about
the genetic mutations.
The doctor?
Still off-line.
We are investigating
the possibility--
Inform me of any progress.
Understood.
There's one more thing.
The incident
with Tom and B'Elanna
started me thinking about
ship's protocol...
or lack thereof.
Captain?
It seems to me that people
have been getting
a little too comfortable
around here lately.
They're late
for their duty shifts,
taking Mess Hall privileges
during non-designated hours,
and a lot of people are spending
more time on the holodeck
than they are at their posts.
You are Security Chief.
Don't 13 department heads
report to you every day?
Yes.
Well, straighten them out.
Shall I flog them as well?
( sighing )
Maybe the doctor was right.
I think I do need a vacation.
You do seem unsettled.
Crazed is more like it.
I haven't felt this anxious
since my first day of command.
( door chimes )
Remind me to lower the volume
on that door. Come in.
Captain, I wish to speak
with you--
What's wrong?
My attempts to repair the
resonance scanner have failed.
I require assistance.
Ask Ensign Kim
to lend you a hand.
Yes, Captain.
Is that all?
( door opens, closes )
When this mutation crisis
is over, I think
I'll spend a few days
in Renaissance Tuscany.
There's a little inn
outside Sienna
I've been wanting to try.
I will join you
for a glass of wine.
( gasps )
DOCTOR:
How many?
SEVEN:
I've observed
56 of the aliens.
There could be more.
DOCTOR:
Have you seen any pattern
to their behavior,
any hint as to what they're
trying to accomplish?
They seem to be conducting
experiments on the crew
and monitoring
the results.
As if Voyager were
one big petri dish.
I may be among them.
In the turbolift,
one of them
probed me with
a medical instrument.
We cannot allow them
to continue.
I've been analyzing
their energy signatures.
I believe there's a way
to make them visible
to everyone.
How?
Using a precisely modulated
phaser beam.
If we expose them,
the crew may be able
to fight back.
But what if the aliens
retaliate
by inflicting lethal mutations
on everyone?
It's too risky.
What do you suggest?
The key to the aliens' control
is the genetic tags.
I believe a neuroleptic shock
would disable them.
Unfortunately, it would be
rather... painful.
Will the crew recover?
Yes, they will.
The hard part will be
administering the shock
to everyone
simultaneously.
The power relays could be
reconfigured to do it.
Good. I assume
you know how to do that?
You assume correctly.
But I will have to bypass
several safeguards.
It will take time.
Then you'd better
get started.
( dramatic theme playing )
( people speaking
indistinctly )
( beeps )
( beeping )
( console beeping )
( com chirps )
Tuvok to Seven of Nine.
SEVEN:
Yes?
Why have you accessed
the EPS relay system?
There is a malfunction.
I'm attempting to repair it.
Perhaps you should leave that
to the Engineering crew.
Normally, I would.
However, they are all occupied
with other tasks.
You are compromising
the power safety protocols.
Stop what you're doing
at once.
I assure you,
there is no cause for concern.
( beeps )
Move away from
the console.
As I told you,
I am conducting repairs.
You are attempting
to deceive me. Why?
I can't explain what I'm doing,
but you must allow me
to continue.
Your actions could result
in an energy discharge,
which would be
harmful to the crew.
I realize that.
Don't move.
If your people attempt
to incapacitate me,
I will kill you.
I believe you.
What do you intend
to do now?
You will come with me
to speak to the Captain.
I am certain she will have
questions for you.
( door opens )
Keep on trying
to disable the tags.
Let me know when you're ready.
Understood.
I'll attempt to modify
the internal sensors
to detect the aliens.
Good.
Keep me informed.
( dramatic theme continues )
Who are you?
And what the hell
are you doing to my crew?
My team has been
observing you
and conducting tests.
Tests?
I'd call them mutilations.
I can understand
why you're angry.
I don't like causing
people to suffer,
but sometimes it's
a necessary part of my work.
What kind of work is that?
Medical research.
We're scientists, like you.
From where I stand,
you're
a hostile invasion force.
I want to know
how long you've been here
and exactly what
you've been doing to us.
I can't answer
those questions.
It's a breach of protocol
for me to be speaking
to you at all.
Oh, how convenient.
( scoffs )
That way you never
have to face your victims.
Captain, please.
You're exaggerating
the situation.
Our techniques are as benign
as we can make them.
What I have been through
for the last few days
certainly hasn't felt benign!
Please understand that there's
a purpose to our actions.
The data we gather from you
may help us cure physical
and psychological disorders
that afflict millions.
Isn't that worth
some discomfort?
I'm sure you'd see things
differently
if your people were the ones
being subjected
to these experiments.
Just as your perspective
would change
if your people were the ones
to live longer and healthier
lives as a result.
Don't forget, we've been
observing you, Captain.
I know the most important
thing to you
is the welfare of your crew.
You'd even kill
to protect them.
If necessary.
Of course you would.
You take care of your own,
just as we do.
We're really more similar
than you care to admit.
That's where you're wrong.
What you're doing
isn't self-defense.
It's the exploitation
of another species
for your own benefit.
My people decided
a long time ago
that that was unacceptable,
even in the name
of scientific progress.
You're a remarkably
strong-willed individual.
I've been very impressed
by your self-control
over the past several weeks.
We've been increasing
your dopamine levels,
stimulating
various aggressive impulses
to test
your behavioral restraints.
There's been a great
difference of opinion
about how much more strain
you can bear.
Not much.
( grunts )
( exhales )
I had hoped you might be
more cooperative
once you realized
the importance of our work.
Sorry. These lab rats
are fighting back.
I'm afraid
that will be pointless.
We're monitoring your attempts
to break our control over you.
You won't succeed.
Well, you may find that
you've underestimated us.
Consider what's in
the best interests of your crew.
We will be continuing
our research.
If you make
no further attempts
to interfere, I assure you
that the fatality rate
will be minimal,
though there may be
some deformities.
And I would be
willing to share
our final data
with you.
You can't possibly expect me
to accept that.
If you don't,
then the entire experiment,
and its subjects
will be terminated.
Are you telling me there is
no way to disable the tags?
My attempts to use
the EPS relays
to induce neuroleptic shock
have failed.
The aliens
may be responsible.
I've encountered
similar difficulties
in my efforts to modify
the internal sensors.
They appear to have gained
access to our key systems.
They can't be everywhere
all the time.
We have got to find
an advantage.
We'd better
find one soon.
Sickbay is being filled
with new patients
with increasingly
severe symptoms.
SEVEN:
We have the ability
to make them visible.
If we could modify
enough sensors,
we could resist them.
They are still capable
of manipulating
our DNA.
A direct conflict
would be inadvisable.
( com chirps )
MAN: Bridge to doctor.
Medical emergency.
( sighs )
( gasping )
( tricorder beeping wildly )
She's in hypertensive shock.
20 milligrams
lectrazine.
Her blood pressure
is 360 over 125.
How is that possible?
DOCTOR:
Severe adrenal stress.
( instrument beeps )
No effect.
Her arterial pathways
are rupturing.
She's in cardiac arrest.
We're losing her.
Captain, I'm afraid
that won't help.
There's too much
internal bleeding.
Then try something else.
We'll transport her to Sickbay.
Her entire circulatory
system has collapsed.
There's no way to repair
that kind of damage.
( tricorder emits steady tone)
Brain death
has occurred.
I'm sorry.
There was nothing more
we could have done.
This ends right now.
You're relieved.
Captain, what
are you doing?
I'm running a little
experiment of my own.
Red Alert!
Captain, one of the aliens
has just entered the Bridge.
Understood.
TUVOK: We're less than
a million kilometers
from the pulsars.
We must change course
immediately
to avoid being caught
in their gravity.
No! Keep going.
This is a far
more reckless course of action
than I've come to expect
from you, Captain.
It certainly is.
Hull stress is at 30 teradynes
and rising.
KIM:
I'm transferring more power
to the structural integrity
field,
but I don't know
how long it can hold.
What do you hope
to accomplish by this?
Flying into a binary pulsar?
It seems like I'm trying
to crush this ship
like a tin can.
It's more likely
that you're trying
to intimidate us.
You're welcome
to stick around and find out.
Hull stress is at 45 teradynes.
Our course is locked in.
Only my authorization
can release it.
You're not behaving
very rationally.
That's what you were trying
to accomplish, wasn't it? Hmm?
Pumping up my dopamine levels
to push me to the edge?
Keeping me awake
for four days straight
with the constant pain
of your devices
drilling into my skull?
Well, this is the culmination
of your work, and guess what?
You're going to be right here
to collect the final data.
KIM:
Shields have failed.
Structural integrity
is down to 20 percent.
Enter the authorization code
and change course
immediately!
I don't think you realize
that you are not
in control here anymore.
I can kill you and your crew
in an instant.
Go ahead.
Without us, you won't be
able to prevent this ship
from being torn apart
by the pulsars.
And even with my crew
working together,
I'd say the odds of us
getting through this
are what? One in ten?
One in 20,
at best, Captain.
I'm willing
to take that chance.
Are you?
Outer hull temperature
has reached 9,000 degrees.
The hull is
beginning to buckle!
( beeping )
Two alien vessels are attempting
to disengage from Voyager.
I can't break us free
of the gravitational forces!
Then let's divert all power
to the shields!
No. If we go in,
we go in full throttle.
Captain?
Assuming we survive,
we're gonna need
all the momentum we can get
to reach escape velocity
on the other side.
Everyone, hang on.
I hope you were exaggerating
about those odds, Tuvok.
I was not.
( dramatic theme playing )
Hull stress has exceeded
maximum tolerance!
There are breaches
on Decks 4, 7, 8 and 12.
Emergency force fields
are holding.
I've lost helm control!
Main power is off-line!
Well, let's hope
we've got enough speed.
I don't believe it.
We're alive.
I never realized you thought
of me as reckless, Tuvok.
A poor choice of words.
It was clearly
an understatement.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51244.3.
With the aliens gone,
the doctor has been able
to remove their devices
from the crew
and neutralize
the genetic tags.
TORRES:
It was nice you could
get the night off.
"Nice" had nothing
to do with it.
I switched shifts
with Ensign Wildman,
which means tomorrow
I'll pull a double-duty
on the Bridge and with the doc.
Well, I appreciate
the sacrifice.
Tell me about the wine.
Ah, Ktarian merlot, 2282.
You might wanna
let it breathe first.
We've got all night
to let it breathe.
( com chirps )
MAN:
Engineering to
Lieutenant Torres.
Torres here.
We are having a problem
with the plasma manifold.
I thought you'd want
to take a look.
I don't.
Lock it down for now.
I'll deal with it
in the morning.
Torres out.
Sometimes it's nice to be
the Chief Engineer.
( chuckles )
Try the salad, Chief.
Hmm.
This is
really delicious.
Well, thanks.
I replicated it myself.
Mm, you're too good
for me.
( door chimes )
Ignore it.
Right.
( door chimes )
I'll get rid of them.
Oh, hi. Uh,
sorry to interrupt.
Hi, B'Elanna.
Harry, I'm not home.
I-I just wanted
to return this.
Thanks.
Smells good!
That's it.
No more interruptions.
You know, heh,
I've been thinking about
what the Captain said.
Thinking maybe she was right?
Me, too.
We have been...
a little out of control
lately.
( both chuckling )
Do you think we really were?
What?
Out of control?
Those aliens could have
just been messing around
with our hormones,
just to see what would happen.
You're right.
They could have.
And we don't know how long
they were on board.
They could have been
tampering with us for months.
Well, when you think about it,
you did have a pretty abrupt
change of heart
a couple of weeks ago.
What made you realize that
you loved me all of a sudden?
Just a feeling.
So, our whole relationship
might be based on some...
alien experiment.
You never know.
Well, I think
that explains it.
I guess we should just...
call it off, then.
I think so.
Thank God
we found out in time.
Thank God.
( romantic theme playing )
I don't know
about you, but...
I'm curious to see how
this experiment turns out.
( triumphant theme playing )