MALE:
Temporal incursion is complete.
All organisms and manmade
objects have been eradicated.
MALE 2:
Probe the continuum.
Has our target
event been achieved?
Negative.
Negative
target event.
I don't understand, sir.
We spent months making
these calculations.
Time is patient...
so we must be
patient with it.
Eradicating
a single Zahl colony
wasn't enough
for a total restoration.
We have to work
on a larger scale.
Take us to the Zahl homeworld.
Prepare a new set
of calculations.
We must erase
the entire species from time,
every life-form...
every molecule.
JANEWAY:
Space, the great unknown.
Only now we're going
to know it a little better.
Harry?
CHAKOTAY:
Before there were
maps and globes,
let alone radar
and subspace sensors,
mariners navigated
by the stars.
We're returning to that
tried-and-true method,
but this time,
there's a difference.
Ensign Kim and
Seven of Nine
have merged Starfleet
and Borg ingenuity
to create this
new technology,
and I'm sure I speak
for the entire crew
when I say... thank you.
Now, how the hell
does it work?
( laughter )
SEVEN:
Astrometric sensors
measure the radiative flux
of up to three billion stars
simultaneously.
The computer
then calculates our position
relative to the center
of the galaxy.
This mapping technology
is ten times more accurate
than what
we've been using.
Seven, will you
do the honors?
We've plotted
a new course home.
By my estimates,
this trajectory will eliminate
five years from
your journey.
Our journey.
Nice work, Seven.
That region of space
we're about to enter,
it looks like it has
a lot of M-Class planets.
It does.
Spatial grid 005.
Primary species: the Zahl.
What do we know
about this species?
Technologically advanced
but nonconfrontational.
Their resistance quotient
is quite low.
Thank you all for coming.
We've got a lot
of work to do, so...
I'd like to say a
few words if I may.
I've prepared a speech
for this occasion.
When I was
first activated
on Stardate 48315,
and I found myself
mano a mano
with the Delta Quadrant,
I didn't think
we'd survive a week
let alone three years.
There was strife.
There was discord.
You were all at
each others' throats,
but over time, I've had the
pleasure and pride
of watching this crew
learn to work together
as colleagues,
even friends.
Here, here.
Who would have thought
that this eclectic group
of voyagers
could actually become a family?
Starfleet, Maquis, Klingon,
Talaxian, hologram, Borg,
even Mr. Paris.
Granted, we've had our share
of difficulties.
One might say, we've seen
the best of times
and the worst of times.
I'd now like to recount
some of those times
from my unique perspective.
Under the category
of "best of times,"
I invite you all to recall
the moment--
Bridge to the Captain.
Janeway here.
We're being hailed.
A vessel off the port bow.
CHAKOTAY:
On our way.
Well, perhaps we could
all reconvene later.
They're firing
on us, Captain.
It's a small vessel,
15 life-forms aboard.
Low warp capacity,
limited armaments.
They pose no threat.
Open a channel.
Good day, sir.
Have we offended
you in some way?
You will reverse course
immediately.
This region is in dispute.
You have no business
in Krenim space.
I was under the impression
we were entering Zahl territory.
The Zahl have
no legitimate claim here.
They have taken what is ours.
Reverse course...
or be destroyed.
With all due respect,
unless you've got
something a little bigger
in your torpedo tubes,
I'm not
turning around,
but I'm certainly
willing to discuss
this issue with you.
No discussion!
No compromise!
They are in retreat.
His bark's obviously worse
than his bite.
He seems rather intent. Let's go
to Yellow Alert.
Maintain our course.
Maybe the Zahl
can give us some answers.
As long as you travel
in Zahl territory,
you travel among friends.
I apologize for your mishap
with the Krenim.
It was hardly traumatic.
But I am curious,
the Krenim claim this
region as their own.
The Krenim dominated
this space many years ago.
They possessed deadly weapons
based on temporal science,
and it kept them in power
for a long time,
but a generation ago,
we fought the Krenim.
We defeated them
and took back the planets
that they had annexed,
dismantled
their military forces.
Their ships still
wander our territory
making grandiose claims.
Don't let them
trouble you.
Now, tell me
about Voyager--
a single ship alone,
half a galaxy from home--
how exciting for you.
KIM: Bridge to Captain.
Sorry to interrupt,
but the Krenim vessel is back.
They're demanding
to speak with you.
Hello again.
You've ignored our warnings,
and now you
consort with our enemy.
Leave this space or
I'll seize your vessel
and send you home
in a cargo container.
Gentlemen, please. Believe me,
we're not conspiring
against you.
( alarm bleeping )
Captain, there's a spatial
distortion heading toward us.
Whatever it is, it's huge.
Five light-years across
and it's expanding.
Tracking its origin.
A vessel near
the Zahl homeworld.
What?
It appears to be
a massive buildup
of temporal energy.
Some kind
of space-time shock wave.
Tom?
It's destabilizing
our warp field.
I've lost engines.
Shields to full.
Secure primary systems.
All hands brace for impact.
She's dead.
TUVOK:
Shields at 17 percent.
The Krenim are
firing again.
We're being hailed.
It's about time.
On screen.
We've done nothing
to provoke these attacks.
Your presence in our space
is provocation enough.
We've been trying to communicate
with your vessels,
but the only answer I get
is weapons fire.
State your identity.
Captain Janeway of the
Federation Starship--
And your reason
for violating our borders.
We're simply trying
to get home.
If you'd kindly allow us
to pass through--
No. You will submit
to the Krenim Imperium.
I would prefer
to seize your vessel
before it is too badly damaged.
Surrender now and I will forego
the execution of your crew.
I don't respond well
to threats.
Then prepare to be boarded.
All hands, battle stations.
This is turning into
the week of hell.
( sighing )
They're charging weapons.
Three seconds to impact.
Evasive maneuvers.
Direct hit to our
secondary hull.
I still don't understand
why these torpedoes
are ripping
right through our shields.
Their weapons are
chroniton-based.
They're penetrating our shields
because they're
in a state of temporal flux.
Then let's exercise
the better part of valor.
Get us out of here, warp 6.
Warp 6.
No sign of pursuit.
Damage report.
Fifteen wounded.
Main power is down.
We've lost environmental control
on Decks 7 and 8.
The computer
is off-line.
Mr. Kim, do we have
any sensors left?
Short-range only.
Commander...
put the ship
on 24-hour Tactical Alert.
Tuvok, analyze
whatever data we've got
on those
chroniton torpedoes.
See if you can
modify our shielding.
When those Krenim
attack again,
I want to be ready.
( door beeps )
Enter.
Sir, you were correct.
The Zahl homeworld
was the focal point.
It's erasure has produced
a complete
temporal restoration.
Complete?
Yes, sir.
If I told you to count
the stars in the cosmos,
would the task ever be complete?
Sir?
Our attempts may
be sufficient.
They may be even
relatively successful,
but they will
never be complete.
Choose your words
with more precision.
My apologies.
What were the exact results?
The Krenim Imperium
has been restored to power.
Our territory
now includes
849 inhabited worlds
spanning 5,000 parsecs.
Counter-indications?
Negligible.
No superior enemy forces.
No unexpected diseases.
Calculations indicate
a 98 percent restoration.
Our race
is thriving once again.
The, uh...
the colony at Kyana Prime...
that was restored as well?
No, sir.
In this timeline,
the Imperium does
not extend that far.
Then our mission has failed.
Begin calculations
for the next incursion.
Sir, we have just accomplished
the impossible--
a 98 percent restoration.
Another incursion,
even a minor one,
could undermine everything.
We should dismantle
this weapon
and rejoin our people.
No, not until
every colony...
every individual...
every blade of
grass is restored.
You said yourself,
our task will never be complete.
Please, we should
be satisfied
with what we have
accomplished.
For 200 years, we have
never come this close.
Not close enough.
If I may speak my thoughts.
Many among the crew
are convinced
that you have lost
your objectivity.
They think your quest
for... precision
is unrealistic.
Sir...
we will never restore
100 percent of what we had.
We can manipulate
the time continuum
for another ten centuries,
it will never happen.
Return to your station and begin
a new set of
calculations.
Is that clear?
Perfectly.
You surprise me, Obrist.
After so many years,
you still perceive time
through conventional eyes.
"Never" is a word that
has no meaning here.
As long as we stay
on this vessel,
protected from space-time,
we have all eternity to
accomplish our mission.
Of course, sir.
JANEWAY: Return fire.
TUVOK: Weapons are down.
My attempt to modify
the shielding was unsuccessful.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain, during that exchange
we did some damage.
Krenim's aft shields
are down. They're vulnerable.
We've got to hit them now!
KIM: With what?
Phaser banks are burned out.
Torpedo launchers are off-line.
Doctor to Bridge.
We've got
a power overload in Sick Bay.
I need an engineer
down here right away.
Stand by, Doctor. Harry, can you
handle it from here?
No, sir.
The overload's spreading.
Half that deck is going to blow
in less than five minutes.
Doctor, get your patients
out of there.
All hands,
this is the Bridge.
Emergency evacuation, Deck 5.
How many torpedoes
do we have left?
Eleven.
Arm four of them.
Stand by
to open the launch doors.
We're going to deploy them
like mines.
Aye, Captain.
Tom, I need
your finesse.
Let the Krenim get within
5,000 meters of us.
No problem.
DOCTOR:
Keep moving.
Quickly. Please,
move quickly.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Structural collapse
in three minutes.
Torpedoes armed and ready.
They're within range.
Tuvok...
do it.
Got 'em!
( alarm beeps )
The conduits
on Deck 5 are overloading.
Thirty seconds till they blow.
DOCTOR: Keep moving.
Please, hurry.
That's it.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Structural collapse
in 20 seconds.
Fifteen seconds!
Warning. Structural collapse
in 10 seconds.
in five...
four...
three... two...
one.
( gasping )
Report!
Sections 10 through 53
on Deck 5...
are gone.
Casualties?
Reports are coming in.
Twelve wounded,
many of them critically.
The Doctor is setting up
a triage facility
in the Mess Hall.
Two crew members were killed
in the breach.
Stand down Red Alert.
Assemble a security team.
Survey the ship deck by deck.
I want a full
damage report.
I'll be in my ready room.
You have the Bridge...
what's left of it.
( buzzing static )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Sorry about the mess.
You should
see my place.
They haven't looked as bad
since my old Academy days.
Is there something
on your mind?
Yes, but you're not
going to like it.
That's never
stopped you before.
Broken.
I'll be blunt.
Our strategy's failing.
It was a good idea
to try and create
temporal shielding,
but it isn't working.
Not yet, but it will.
With every attack,
we gather more information
about their chroniton weapons.
How many more attacks
will it take?
Before long, there won't be
a ship left to protect.
We don't have a choice.
Maybe we do.
Here comes the part
I'm not going to like.
We should consider
leaving the ship behind,
breaking the crew into smaller
groups-- escape pods, shuttles--
each one with its own course.
If all goes well,
we'll rendezvous
on the other side
of Krenim space.
Then what?
We'll cross that bridge
when we come to it,
but at least we'd be increasing
our chances of survival.
Abandon ship?
The answer's no.
I'm not breaking up
the family, Chakotay.
We're stronger as a team.
One crew, one ship.
The moment we split apart,
we lose the ability
to pool our talents.
We become vulnerable.
We'll get picked off one by one.
Now, I say we make
our stand together.
To be honest, I wasn't too fond
of the idea myself.
As long as Voyager's
in one piece,
we stay.
( sighs )
We stay.
This looks like
it stayed in one piece.
Where does this go?
My lucky teacup.
Right over here.
PARIS:
Red Alert.
We're under attack.
Two Krenim warships
off the port bow.
( rattling )
TORRES:
When are they going
to get us out of here?
KIM:
Try to relax.
Let's get back to the game.
Grace Kelly...
cat burglars... the Riviera.
Name the title...
and the male lead.
To Catch a Thief.
Right.
Clark Gable.
( imitates buzzer )
Wrong. Cary Grant.
I've seen
the holographic version twice.
It's Clark Gable.
I think you're getting them
confused
because they have the same
initials. It was Grant.
No more
20th-century entertainment.
I'm terrible at it.
My turn.
Category... athletics.
Fire away.
A notorious athlete...
parrises' squares,
championship finals...
uh... controversial decision.
M'Kota R'Cho, the first and only
Klingon to ever play the game.
During the finals of 2342,
one of the referees
called a penalty
against his team.
R'Cho strangled him.
Impressive.
You're looking at a true
sports aficionado.
Let's see... how about
interstellar history?
Oh, great. You pick
the one subject
I almost failed at the Academy.
Go ahead and ask--
( groans )
Hey, you all right?
Mm-hmm.
( gasping )
It just...
hurts a little.
( breathing rapidly )
It feels like we've
been here for days.
Actually, it's been
about six hours.
Try to hang on,
B'Elanna.
The emergency crews are
going to find us any minute.
Come on, hurry up!
Go ahead and ask
your stupid question,
before I pass out
and you don't have
anybody to play with.
Okay.
Um... it's a famous ship.
Uh... pre-warp civilization...
um... Montana...
uh... second stage
had chemical engines.
Another clue.
Vulcans, um...
Earth...
first contact.
Oh, right, right.
Um... uh... uh...
Zephram Cochrane's ship...
What was it called?
God, it's on the tip
of my tongue.
( groaning )
Okay, okay. Here,
you better lie down now.
Enough trivia for now.
No. No, I'm going
to get this one.
( thumping )
Lieutenant. Ensign.
It's about time.
What happened
to the turbolift?
During the last attack,
19 main power relays
were severed.
The entire turbolift system
is nonoperational.
Get me to the Jefferies tube
network on Deck 11.
The EPS manifold
must have taken a hit too.
Seven of Nine
can go take a look.
We have to get you
to the Doctor.
All right.
The Phoenix.
What?
The correct response
to your query.
The vessel Ensign Kim
was describing.
It was designated
the Phoenix.
Not bad.
I didn't realize
you knew so much
about Earth history.
I don't, but the Borg
were present
during those events.
Really?
It's a complicated
story.
Perhaps another time.
I think so.
Transverse bulkheads.
We've set up
emergency force fields
between all decks
and every section.
In the event
of a cataclysmic breach,
most of us
will be protected.
Ingenious.
Actually, you can
thank Mr. Paris.
He came up
with the idea.
I was inspired by
an ancient steamship,
the Titanic.
The engineers of the day
constructed a series
of special bulkheads--
sort of like
a honeycomb--
that would lower into place
if they suffered
a major hull breach.
In theory,
they could stay afloat
even with half the ship
filled with water.
The Titanic?
As I recall, it sank.
Well, let's just say,
I've made a few
improvements.
I knew your fixation
with history
would come in handy
someday. Good work.
Doctor to Lieutenant Paris.
Go ahead, Doc.
Report to the Mess Hall
at once.
More wounded are on the way.
I'll be right there. I'm a
popular guy today.
( beeping denial )
Seven of Nine to Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
There is an undetonated
chroniton torpedo
lodged in the starboard
Jefferies tube
on Deck 11, Section 2.
The warhead is still active.
Do not attempt to disarm it.
Hold your position
and wait for my arrival.
Is that clear?
Arrive quickly.
( breathing heavily )
I've stopped the
internal bleeding.
You're going
to be okay.
Is that your expert opinion?
That's a promise.
I know.
It still hurts.
No, it's all right.
You've got
a ruptured vertebra.
I'll see if I can repair it.
Mr. Paris, your
assistance, please.
Give me a minute.
Now, Lieutenant.
I'll be right back.
Don't go anywhere.
In case
you hadn't noticed,
B'Elanna is not
the only patient here.
She's in pain.
But no longer
in danger of dying.
That is the first rule
of medical triage.
Make sure
the patient will live,
then move on
to the next one.
Emotional detachment
is essential.
Otherwise, you risk
impairing your judgment.
I understand.
You could be seeing more
of your friends
in here soon.
If you can't
handle it,
I'll find
another assistant.
You can leave.
"Physician,
heal thyself."
What's that
supposed to mean?
Well, it seems to me
that you're the one
who's getting emotional
around here.
Several weeks ago,
just before the conduits
on Deck 5 breached,
I saw Ensign Strickler
and Crewman Emmanuel
at the end
of a corridor.
They were... trying to reach the
Jefferies tube.
I kept
the hatch open,
waited for them
as long as I could,
but time ran out.
I had no choice
but to seal the hatch.
That must have been very hard
for you.
My point is, it
could have been worse.
Had I lost my objectivity, I
might have kept the hatch open
and everyone
would have perished.
This man has
damaged lung tissue.
Treat him with
inaprovaline.
If we attempt
to dislodge the torpedo
or move it
with the transporters,
it will
most likely detonate.
Can we disarm it?
No. The warhead
is already destabilizing.
I estimate it will explode
in less than two minutes.
If we reroute emergency
power to this junction,
and erect a level-10
force field,
it should be enough
to contain the explosion.
We must hurry.
If I can determine the exact
temporal variance of this
torpedo, it will help us
perfect the temporal shielding.
There is no time.
We may never have
this opportunity again.
I am giving you
an order. Now!
The temporal variance
is 1.47 microseconds.
Excellent work.
But if you disobey
my orders again,
I will be forced to--
( loud crackling )
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51268.4.
This morning's attack destroyed
the power grid on Deck 11.
No casualties this time,
but the replicator system
was badly damaged.
We've gone
to emergency rations.
As a result, the situation
has gotten a little worse.
Environmental controls
continue to fail.
Seven decks have been rendered
uninhabitable
and we've had
to relocate the crew.
Quarters are close,
nerves are frayed,
and I'm not sure what's
more difficult to maintain--
Voyager's systems
or the crew's morale.
What's important
is that we're together,
working towards
a single goal. Survival.
CHAKOTAY:
Happy birthday.
Happy what?
Today is May 20.
Is it?
I thought
we were still in April.
Guess I've lost
track of the time.
Well, this should help.
It's beautiful.
Nineteenth century,
mechanical movement.
It's a replica
of the chronometer
worn by Captain Cray
of the British Navy.
His ship was hit
by a typhoon in the Pacific.
Everyone back in England
thought they were killed,
but eight months later,
Cray sailed his ship
into London harbor.
There wasn't much left of it,
a few planks, half a sail,
but he got his crew home.
I appreciate the sentiment,
but I can't keep this.
Recycle it.
We can't afford to waste energy
on nonessentials.
Kathryn, I replicated this
months ago.
I've been saving it.
I wanted you to have it.
That watch represents a meal,
a hypospray or a pair of boots.
It could mean the difference
between life and death one day.
( door chimes )
Enter.
Reporting for duty,
Lieutenant.
What is our agenda?
After we make
your customary rounds,
I'd like to take you
to Deflector Control.
I had an inspiration last night
about the temporal shielding.
Excellent.
You've been damaged.
A minor laceration.
I've offered to assist you
with your personal grooming.
There are some tasks I would
rather perform myself.
Unacceptable.
You're risking further injury.
Shaving is hardly a
life-threatening activity.
Tell me about
your inspiration.
We've been trying
to match our shields
to the temporal variance
of their torpedoes.
But I believe we must
also match the deflector array
to the inverse of that variance.
Fascinating. When will
the deflectors be ready?
They're ready now, but the
modifications are untested.
Then our rounds can wait.
Take me to Deflector Control.
Seven.
Ensign.
A friend of yours?
My... cabin mate.
As a Borg, I was accustomed
to cohabitating
with thousands
of other drones.
But I find it significantly
more difficult
to live with
a single human.
In what way?
Ensign Brooks
is negligent.
She leaves her equipment
lying around the quarters
and her clothing
on the floor.
Indeed. I have found that most
humans are less than meticulous
when it comes
to their domestic habits.
Indeed.
Mr. Vulcan, sir.
A tactical question if I may?
You may.
We're just about done rebuilding
the internal security sensors
and we're ready
to program the audio signal.
Do you want it to say,
"intruder alert"?
Or should we try something
a little more dramatic
like "warning,
intruder alert"?
Or... "intruders
among us, danger!
Danger! Intruders
among us"?
"Intruder alert"
will suffice.
Yeah, go with a classic.
Understood, sir.
And you believe
you have difficulties.
( alarm blares )
CHAKOTAY:
All hands to battle stations.
Krenim vessels approaching.
Repeat: all hands
to battle stations!
Go to Deflector Control and
bring the new shields on line.
We will test them in battle.
Computer, activate tactile
interface.
CHAKOTAY:
Weapons status?
( console beeping )
Phasers are still on line.
Torpedo launchers
are inoperative.
PARIS:
The Krenim are
within visual range.
On screen.
TUVOK:
Seven's modified
temporal shields
should be on line
in a moment.
It's a warship.
You know the routine.
Evasive maneuvers.
They're matching course.
Hold them off
as long as you can.
Bridge to Seven of Nine.
Where are those shields?
Stand by.
They're charging weapons.
Seven, we could use a little
of that Borg efficiency
right about now.
I can't shake them off!
They're targeting the Bridge!
Temporal shielding is on line.
They're firing!
Full port thrusters!
Temporal shields are holding.
No damage.
Hail them.
Channel open.
Krenim vessels,
this is the Captain of Voyager.
You may have noticed
we have a defense
against your torpedoes now.
I suggest you stand down.
No response.
Their mistake.
Bring the ship about.
We're going through their space
whether they like it or not.
We are within range
of the Garenor homeworld.
Set temporal coordinates.
Full power to the weapon.
Prepare for total erasure
of the species.
Targeting the focal point.
Ready.
Fire.
Temporal incursion in progress.
Trace elements?
Diminishing.
Counter-indications?
None so far.
Organisms and structures
are being eradicated.
Track the temporal wave front
as it passes
through their system.
I want to monitor every change
in the timeline as it occurs.
Yes, sir.
Captain, the Krenim warship
is in pursuit,
but their weapons
are not powered.
Hmm. They don't know
what to do with us
now that we're shielded
against their torpedoes.
( console beeps )
Captain, there's some kind
of spatial distortion
heading toward us.
Sensor readings
are erratic.
I can't identify
the phenomenon.
What's the source?
Unknown,
but it originated approximately
20 light-years
from our position.
It looks like a shock wave
in the fabric of space-time.
Tom, get us out of here.
We'll never outrun it, Captain.
Maybe our new shields will help.
All hands, brace for impact.
You were correct, Captain.
The temporal shielding
has protected us.
The wave front has passed.
Captain?
Report.
It's definitely a Krenim ship.
Identical hull markings,
same biospectral frequency...
but it's half the size. Limited
fire power.
What happened to the warship?
I'm not picking it up
on long-range sensors.
CHAKOTAY:
It looks like this entire part
of space has changed somehow.
The last time I checked,
this region was filled
with Krenim colonies
and vessels.
I just ran a scan and
sensors show no colonies
and just a handful
of Krenim ships.
Harry, transfer all your sensor
data about that shock wave
to the Astrometrics Lab.
Yes, ma'am.
Tell Seven of Nine
to meet me there.
Captain, Astrometrics
took heavy damage
a few days go.
It's off-line.
Well, let's get it back on line.
It appears that the Krenim
Imperium has vanished.
Our troubles could be over
and I'd like to find out why.
Something went wrong.
The entire Krenim Imperium,
it's reverted
to a pre-warp state.
Not possible.
Our calculations were perfect.
( console beeping )
I may have an explanation.
There's an anomalous
temporal reading
20 light-years from here.
It's coming
from a vessel.
What vessel?
Component 049-beta,
a ship called Voyager.
That ship was classified
as an inert component.
It shouldn't be generating
a temporal field.
But it is...
and it was enough to throw
off our calculations.
Take me to them.
Sensors are on line.
Power levels are stable.
Is the astrometric database
still intact?
( console beeping )
Yes.
Display the scans
we made of this region
before the temporal
shock wave hit.
Spatial grid 005.
The Krenim Imperium.
Over 200 star systems,
900 planets,
thousands of warp-capable
vessels and now...
after the shock wave,
everything seems
to have changed.
Run a new scan.
Spatial grid 005.
Same space,
different configuration.
Exactly as Chakotay said.
The Imperium
appears to have been reduced
to a few planets,
and a smattering of vessels.
It appears that someone...
or something
has altered history.
But why weren't we affected?
Perhaps we were protected
from the changes
by our temporal shielding.
Mmm.
So the question remains:
What caused that shock
wave in the first place?
See if you can track
it back to its origin.
The shock wave emanated from
a planet 20 light-years away.
The Garenor homeworld.
The Garenor?
We passed their planet
three weeks ago.
The planet
is no longer populated.
What?
Astrometric data
indicate
that the instant
the shock wave appeared,
the Garenor species
vanished.
( whispering ):
Erased from history.
Captain?
I'm no authority
on time travel.
In fact, I've made it my goal
in life to avoid it, but...
this sounds to me like
a causality paradox.
Think about it.
A temporal shock wave
eliminates a single species
and all of history
changes as a result.
An intriguing theory.
Perhaps the Krenim
are responsible.
They do possess
temporal technology.
But why would they alter history
to undermine themselves?
No, we're still missing
a big piece of the puzzle.
Run another scan of the--
( deep rumbling )
Scanning the vessel.
Their defensive shielding
is generating a level-9
temporal disruption.
Collect samples.
Two life-forms,
ten square meters of the hull.
Yes, sir.
Disable their shielding.
Prepare to initiate
a temporal incursion.
That entire vessel's
in a state of temporal flux.
It's like they exist
outside space-time.
They're scanning us.
Get a lock on them!
I'm trying, but I can't
isolate their signals.
We are being hailed.
JANEWAY: On screen.
State your identity.
I'm Captain Janeway of the
Federation Starship Voyager.
Who are you,
and where are my men?
I am Annorax
of the Krenim Imperium.
We've transferred your crewmen
to my vessel
for further analysis.
Your ship does not come
from this Quadrant.
We come from Earth.
A planet 65,000
light-years from here.
We're on our way home.
I see.
We've been observing
some rather...
unusual events in the region.
It seems your Imperium... never
existed.
Perhaps you could shed
some light on this.
That doesn't concern you.
What is important
is that you understand
that I bear you no hostility...
but you have diverted me
from my mission.
Your mission?
You're responsible for
the changes in the timeline.
You're a long way
from your world.
In a manner of speaking,
so am I.
Unfortunately, only one of us
can go home again.
Your sacrifice will restore
the lives
of countless millions.
I'm sorry.
KIM:
I'm reading a massive
energy buildup.
Some kind of weapon.
Shields.
Temporal shields are weakening.
Captain, that energy beam,
it's pushing Voyager out of
the space-time continuum.
He's trying to erase us
from history.
SEVEN:
I have scanned
their propulsion system.
Their vessel's mass prevents
them from exceeding warp 6.
We can escape.
Captain, I must remind you,
our structural integrity
is still impaired.
If we go to warp now, the damage
to Voyager will be extreme.
What about Tom and Chakotay?
We'll have to come back
for them.
All hands
clear the outer sections
and prepare
for wide-scale breaches.
Tuvok, activate
the transverse bulkheads.
Temporal shields are failing.
Engage warp 7.
They're not in pursuit.
We are losing the outer hull.
Transverse bulkheads
are holding.
JANEWAY:
Each of you has
done your best,
but determination alone
isn't going to hold
this ship together.
It's time we faced reality.
We've lost nine decks.
More than half the ship
has been destroyed.
Life support is nearly gone.
Voyager can no longer
sustain its crew.
I promised myself that I
would never give this order,
that I would never break up
this family,
but asking you to stay...
would be asking you to die.
You will proceed
to the escape pods,
and evacuate this vessel.
Set your course
for the Alpha Quadrant.
Along the way,
try to find allies.
Secure faster ships if you can.
Anything to get home.
The senior staff and I
will remain on board
as long as possible.
We will try, somehow,
to rescue Tom and Chakotay.
The escape pods are equipped
with subspace beacons.
That's how we'll
keep track of you.
When we find each other again,
and we will...
we will find
each other again--
I expect all of you
to be in one piece
with some interesting stories
to tell.
Good luck.