NARRATOR:
Last time,
on Star Trek: Voyager...
CHAKOTAY:
Looks like this
entire part of space
has changed somehow.
We should dismantle
this weapon
and rejoin our people.
No, not until
every colony...
every individual...
every blade of
grass is restored.
It appears that someone...
or something
has altered history.
Captain, that energy beam,
it's pushing Voyager out
of the space-time continuum.
He's trying to erase us
from history.
I promised myself that I
would never give this order,
that I would never break up
this family,
but asking you to stay...
would be asking you to die.
NARRATOR:
And now, the conclusion.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51425.4.
Our condition has left us
vulnerable to spatial
anomalies,
and to any alien species
eager for a piece of hardware.
We've taken refuge
in a class-9 nebula.
( alarm beeping )
( beeps denial )
Oh, come on!
Don't do this to me now.
Emergency force fields
are holding.
How the hell did all
this gas get inside?
KIM:
Looks like a malfunction
in the ventilation system.
Okay, I'm going to try
reversing the osmotic pressure
on this deck.
Oh!
Whoa!
The gas corroded
the circuit relays.
Let's bypass.
( coughing )
We've got three
minutes of air left.
How long can you
hold your breath?
( coughing )
Ensign Kim found time
to be treated, so can you.
How is Harry?
He'll be fine,
but I'm surprised
he didn't asphyxiate.
I told you eight
minutes on that deck,
not eight and a half, not
nine, and certainly not 12.
Would you rather have
an indoor nebula?
If we didn't stop it
then and there,
it would have flooded
another two decks.
B'Elanna, engines?
Not yet, Captain.
One of the warp nacelles
is still off-line.
The other one's
a lost cause.
Route all available power
to the good one.
( coughing )
The alveoli in your lungs
have been chemically burned.
I want you off your feet
for the next 48 hours.
Impossible. I've got
too much work to do.
There are seven other
crew members on board.
You're the Captain.
Delegate.
Inject me with trioxin.
That should help me
breathe a little easier.
B'Elanna, stand by
for the transfer.
Right.
Trioxin is used
in emergency situations
as a stopgap measure.
Your lungs have suffered
serious damage.
They need to be
treated properly.
Doctor's orders.
Captain's orders,
trioxin, now.
Aye, aye.
It's your body.
Who am I to judge?
I'm only the Chief
Medical Officer.
What do I know?
Thank you.
Now, where were we?
( coughing violently )
( door opens )
Well...
you look rested.
Where's my crewmate?
He should have been here by now.
No doubt he's making
himself difficult.
I've never seen such
an intransigent young man.
You've had us in isolation
for two months.
We've been scanned,
poked and prodded.
How do you
expect us to act?
With some degree
of dignity and restraint.
Your crewmate has none.
What do you want from us?
At the moment...
information.
Anything for such
a charming host.
Are you all right?
The galley
has prepared
a selection
of unique delicacies.
You won't find them
anywhere else in the galaxy.
Please, join me.
Malkothian spirits,
an extremely rare vintage.
The only bottle
known to exist.
Your Captain
said that...
your vessel is trying
to reach home.
I hadn't realized
how far your home was.
You're an anomalous component,
alone, disconnected,
impossible to predict.
You have no idea how you've
complicated my mission.
Glad to hear it.
When I first encountered
your vessel,
it was badly damaged,
barely functioning.
What if I told you,
that in the blink of an eye,
I could restore Voyager
to its former condition?
That you and I
would never have met?
That you might
even find yourself
closer to the Alpha Quadrant?
By using the weapon on this ship
to alter history.
Yes.
I can control
the destiny of a...
single molecule
or an entire civilization.
How's the wine?
Excellent.
This bottle is
the only component left
of the once powerful
Malkoth race.
Everything else about them,
cities, culture,
the very species itself,
never existed...
because of me.
Every dish you see here
comes from
a civilization that...
has been erased from time.
Mr. Paris,
you're devouring
the last remnants
of the Alsuran Empire.
I have collected artifacts
from...
hundreds of worlds.
This vessel is
more than a weapon.
It's a museum of lost histories.
You two gentlemen almost became
artifacts yourselves.
But I've decided to...
spare your vessel.
Why?
Call it an act
of compassion.
You're trying to reach home.
In a way, so am I.
We can work together
to achieve both our goals.
What do you propose?
In order to make
the calculations required
to restore Voyager,
I need to know
about some of your experiences
in this Quadrant.
What species
you interacted with,
how other components were
affected by your presence...
You can't find her,
can you?
I think Captain Janeway
has been eluding you
for the past two months.
Otherwise, you
would've destroyed
Voyager by now.
I'm offering you
a way out of this situation.
You accept my offer...
or when I do find Voyager,
I will destroy it.
And how many civilizations
will you have to erase
to send us merrily
on our way?
No, thanks.
We don't want that kind
of blood on our hands.
Tom, hold on.
You said you
could control
the destiny of a
single molecule.
If you made a precise
enough calculation,
could you restore Voyager
without harming anyone?
It is possible...
but it's extremely difficult.
That's why I need
your cooperation.
( scoffs )
I'd rather spend a year
in solitary confinement
than listen to any of this.
Tom, have a seat.
Chakotay,
we can't trust him.
You're correct.
Given the circumstances,
there is no reason to trust me,
but trust isn't necessary.
We need each other.
( beeping )
Obrist...
show our guest
to his new quarters.
I'll do everything
in my power
to make you comfortable
here, Mr. Paris.
All I ask in return...
is that you keep an open mind.
I was very impressed
with your question.
You seem to understand
the subtleties of time.
Professor Vassbinder
might've disagreed with you.
I failed his course
in temporal mechanics.
Beyond study
and instrumentation,
there is instinct.
Not everyone has the ability
to truly perceive time...
its colors, its moods.
Perhaps you do.
I'm certainly willing
to give it a try.
TORRES:
To distant friends.
NEELIX:
To friends.
JANEWAY: Hear, hear.
KIM: Cheers.
Well?
Interesting.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
What...is it exactly?
I call it
"the elixir of endurance."
It's loaded with amino acids,
carbohydrates,
all the nutrients
necessary for the crew
to withstand these
stressful conditions.
Ration cubes.
Well, yes, yes, but
this time, pureed,
and mixed with water,
and enhanced
with Talaxian spices.
It is offensive.
( chuckles )
Fortunately,
taste is irrelevant.
Well, it's been a few days
since we've gathered
in one place.
Now's a good time to catch up.
How are the repairs proceeding?
DOCTOR:
I'm happy to report
that I've repaired the optronic
error in my program.
And the power grid?
We're operating
at 32 percent efficiency.
I think I can bring it up to 50,
but I'll need a few more days.
Warp drive?
I'm still having trouble
with the starboard nacelle.
How long?
Three weeks, minimum.
( sighs )
I thought this nebula
would be a safe haven
until we finished repairs,
but it's turning
into a permanent residence.
We've got to get back
into open space,
find allies,
put together
a fighting force
to take on Annorax.
We're leaving
this damn cloud
first thing tomorrow morning.
SEVEN:
Captain,
you are in error.
Really?
At the moment,
this vessel is defenseless.
We should remain here
until we are functioning
at our peak efficiency.
I appreciate your opinion,
Seven, but I disagree.
We leave tomorrow,
0800 hours.
It is inappropriate to
contradict the Captain
in front of the crew.
That was not
my intention.
I simply pointed out
that her decision was wrong.
In your view.
And yours.
I know you well enough
to say that.
Then you should also know
that my trust
in Captain Janeway is absolute.
The decision you or I
might have made is irrelevant.
As a Borg, I submitted
to a single authority,
the collective.
Over the past several months,
I've been encouraged
to think and act
as an individual.
It is difficult
to know
when to restrain myself.
Remember this guideline,
The Captain is always right.
Even when you know
her logic is flawed?
Perhaps.
CHAKOTAY:
Component 37329, a rogue comet.
About eight months ago,
Voyager made
a course correction
to avoid the comet.
According to
my calculations,
it led to our
entering Krenim space.
Your solution, then, would be to
erase that comet from history.
Exactly.
Voyager would have
stayed on its course,
and bypassed Krenim
space altogether.
Sounds simple enough.
Conduct a simulation.
Temporal incursion
in progress.
What happened?
Had you actually
eradicated that comet,
all life within
50 light-years
would never
have existed.
Congratulations.
You almost wiped out...
8,000 civilizations.
I didn't consider
the entire history
of the comet.
Four billion years ago,
fragments from that comet
impacted a planet.
Hydrocarbons
from those fragments
gave rise to
several species
of plant life,
which in turn,
sustained more
complex organisms.
Ultimately, several
space-faring civilizations
evolved and colonized
the entire sector.
By erasing the comet,
I altered all evolution
in this region.
Past, present and future...
they exist as one.
They breathe together.
You're not the only person
to make this mistake.
When I first constructed
this weapon ship,
I turned it against
our greatest enemy,
the Rilnar.
The result
was miraculous.
With the Rilnar
gone from history,
my people, in an instant,
became powerful again,
but there were problems.
A rare disease broke out
among our colonies.
Within a year,
50 million were dead.
I had failed to realize
that the Rilnar
had introduced
a crucial antibody
into the Krenim genome...
and my weapon
had eliminated
that antibody as well.
And you've been trying
to undo that damage
ever since,
but each time you
pull out a new thread,
another one
begins to unravel.
You can't imagine the burden
of memory that I carry,
thousands of worlds,
billions of lives,
gone, brought back,
gone again.
I try to rationalize the loss.
They're not
really being destroyed,
because they never existed.
Sometimes I can...
almost convince myself.
You've been at this
for 200 years, Annorax.
What makes you think
you're ever going to succeed?
What makes you think Voyager
will ever reach Earth?
The odds against you
are astronomical.
Yet, you keep trying.
You're right, but we
don't destroy everything
that stands in our way.
You can help me to
change that, Chakotay.
Together, we'll restore
the Krenim and Voyager,
and we'll undo the
damage that I've caused.
I've still got a lot to learn.
Come.
It's time I show you
the heart of this vessel,
the temporal core.
( slow theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Engines?
I'm doing my best!
Captain, with
the deflector down,
those micro-meteoroids
are beginning to
erode the hull.
Emergency power
to the deflector.
None available.
( thumps and bangs on hull )
I'll be in Deflector Control.
TUVOK:
Captain, that
entire section
has been designated
hazard-level 4.
I know.
( suspenseful theme plays )
( screams )
Oh, why do I get the feeling
you're testing me, Voyager?
Bridge, there's a fire
in Deflector Control.
Any luck with the engines?
The warp core's still off-line.
Micro-meteoroid density
is increasing.
The nacelle pylon
is buckling.
Bridge, I'm going in.
Stand by
to engage the deflector.
Tell the Doctor I'll be coming
back with severe burns.
Captain...
Do it.
Be kind.
( rumbling )
The Captain's accessed
manual control.
She's stabilizing
the particle emitters.
( beeping )
She's got it.
Deflector's on line.
Activating deflector field.
Bridge to Janeway.
Captain,
please respond.
( moaning )
What's my condition?
You suffered
third-degree burns
to approximately
60 percent of your body.
I've healed most of them,
but without a
dermal regenerator,
I couldn't repair all
the damage to your skin.
You've been left with scars
on your face and arms.
( sighs )
I'll consider
them mementos.
Not so fast.
You're spending
the next few days
here with me.
What for?
Observation.
Is there something else
wrong with me?
Not physically.
What are you suggesting?
Traumatic stress syndrome.
Symptoms, irritability,
sleeplessness,
obsessional thoughts,
reckless behavior...
all of which you've demonstrated
over the last few weeks.
My only obsession is with
saving my ship, my people.
If I've been taking
some reckless chances
in order to do that, it's
hardly a medical condition.
I'm not going to stand
here while you rationalize
yet another brush with death.
You don't have to.
As Chief Medical Officer,
I have the authority to
relieve you of your command.
You're not going to do that.
If, in my medical opinion,
your judgment has been
impaired, I can and I will.
Try it and I'll shut
down your program.
That threat in itself
is evidence of your
unstable condition.
I am sorry, Doctor.
I've been operating
on instinct for so long,
I did not think
before I spoke.
I have no intention
of deactivating you,
but I won't stay
in this Mess Hall.
Is that final?
Final.
Then you leave me
no choice.
Captain Kathryn Janeway,
under Starfleet Medical
Regulation 121, Section A,
I, the Chief Medical Officer,
do hereby relieve you
of your active command,
effective immediately.
Have a seat.
How do you plan to implement
this protocol, Doctor?
Mr. Tuvok doesn't have
a security team,
both the brigs
have been destroyed,
and with the internal
force fields off-line,
you'll have a hell of a time
keeping me confined.
You'd better
grab a phaser,
because before
I give up command,
you'll have to shoot me.
You realize this incident will
be noted in my official logs.
By refusing my orders, you risk
a general court martial.
Compared to what I've been
through the past few months,
a court martial would be
a small price to pay.
If we make it back home...
I'll be happy to face the music.
Another ruptured
EPS conduit.
Thirty two so far...
33, 34, 35...
And that fluidic converter
needs to be purged.
Right.
The gravitational plating
in this room has buckled.
Chakotay's quarters.
( tricorder beeping softly )
( beeping intensifies )
You disobeyed orders.
Captain?
Chakotay gave this
to me five months ago,
a birthday gift.
I ordered him to--
What do you think?
Handsome.
Come on.
Astounding.
Not really.
I get lucky
now and again.
Uh, your end game
sequence, it, uh...
it was the same one
favored by my brother.
To quote a long lost
friend of mine,
"It seemed logical."
Now what?
I used to honor
the day of his birth.
Who?
My brother.
And my parents,
my closest friends.
Every year, at first.
Then one day,
I realized,
a century had passed...
and for years, I had been
celebrating birthdays...
for the dead.
Mmm.
Or for people
who never even existed.
I'm sorry.
You can put that
thing down, Chakotay.
No need to strain
your eyes anymore.
I've got a plan.
Let's hear it.
This ship's
temporal core
keeps the vessel out of phase
with normal space-time,
but its shields
are incredibly weak.
You take that core off-line,
and a photon grenade
could penetrate
the hull.
How do you know all this?
I've been spending time
with our friend Obrist,
who seems more than willing
to share information.
And that's not all.
Does the name Captain Bligh
mean anything to you?
This is not a happy crew.
They've been at this
for 200 years now.
They're tired of it, Chakotay.
They want it to end.
Good work, Tom,
but I'm not quite ready
to start a mutiny.
Keep gathering
information.
Lie low.
I'm starting
to make progress
on the temporal
calculations.
With a little
time and luck,
I think we can get the
Krenim back on their feet,
and Voyager back to
the Alpha Quadrant.
You're starting to sound
like Annorax,
always one more calculation.
This time it's going
to be perfect.
This can work.
If you'd take time to listen,
you'd understand what Annorax
is trying to do.
What? Wipe out civilizations
to help his own race?
I understand perfectly.
It's more complicated than that.
Annorax is an
enlightened man,
misguided, but I think
he wants this to end
as much as anyone.
I guess I don't have
the instinct for time,
or whatever it is Captain Nemo
out there calls it.
Chakotay, he's been
flattering you
and it's gone to your head.
You're out of line,
Lieutenant.
( sighs )
Maybe I shouldn't
start a mutiny,
but I might be able
to get Obrist
to help us send a message
to Captain Janeway.
Not yet, if you get caught,
we lose everything.
I can get us out of this.
Not if I can get us
out of here first.
You're not doing anything
against Annorax.
That's an order.
( scoffs )
What are you going to do,
take away
my holodeck privileges?
Either we maintain
our command structure,
or else
we settle our differences
the old-fashioned way.
( alarm blaring )
What's happening?
We're preparing for
a temporal incursion.
What incursion?
You didn't
say anything...
I had an inspiration
last night.
By my calculations,
the eradication of
the Ram Izad species
will result
in a 52 percent restoration
of the Krenim timeline.
I thought we were working
to avoid more destruction.
When time offers you
an opportunity,
you don't ignore it.
We're within range
of their homeworld.
Take us into orbit.
Full power
to the weapon.
Prepare for
total erasure.
Is this what you call
enlightened?
Targeting the focal point.
Locked.
Please, this isn't necessary.
We'll find another way.
Fire.
Trace elements?
Diminishing.
Counter-indications.
None so far.
Scan the continuum.
Bring me the results
once they're complete.
Yes, sir.
I'll be in my chambers.
Have you seen enough
yet, Chakotay?
If you don't do something
about this maniac, I will.
You didn't need to
fire on that planet.
I'm altering history
on a massive scale.
The destinies of countless
star systems are in my hands.
The fate of one species
is insignificant.
You're trying
to rationalize genocide.
One species is significant.
A single life is significant.
It seemed so...
easy the first time.
In the blink of an eye,
I had changed history itself,
allowed my people
to thrive again.
But when I changed history
a second time...
I lost more
than you can imagine.
The colony on Kyana Prime.
How could you know that?
I've been studying
your previous incursions.
No matter how close you get
to restoring the timeline,
one component
is always missing...
Kyana Prime.
Who was on that colony?
Who did you lose?
My wife...
and with her, my future.
My children,
grandchildren,
all erased because of me.
This is all
I have left of her.
So many years
I worked through the night
while she was sleeping.
How could I have known I was...
calculating her fate?
I can't stop
until I've restored Kyana Prime,
and forced time
to give me back my wife.
Maybe it isn't possible.
When I tell you
that time has moods...
a disposition to be intuited...
I'm not speaking metaphorically.
What do you mean?
Anger is one of its moods,
anger and the desire for...
retribution, vengeance.
Time itself has tried
to punish me for my arrogance.
It has kept me from my wife,
denied me my future.
Sir, we've achieved
a 52 percent restoration.
Kyana Prime?
Negative, sir.
Resume scanning
the continuum.
OBRIST:
Yes, sir.
( door closes )
( clears throat ):
I've, uh...
I've studied your
calculations, Chakotay.
They're promising...
premature.
We'll keep working on them.
In the meantime,
my mission must continue.
You don't
have the right--
To fight for what is mine?
That's not for you to decide.
Only time can pronounce
judgment against me.
( sighs )
If that little display
doesn't convince you,
I don't know what will.
He's insane.
No, he's not.
Wounded maybe,
even tortured,
but I can still reach him...
convince him to stop.
Not from what you've told me.
This guy thinks that time has
a personal grudge against him.
That's called paranoia,
Chakotay,
with a hint of megalomania.
You don't know
what he's been through.
He's lost his family.
Okay, that's a terrible thing,
but so has everyone else
on this ship,
and frankly, so have we!
What kind of progress
have you made?
Obrist is coming around...
and I think we can trust him.
He says he'll give me access
to their communications array.
I can send a message to Voyager
from the comfort
of my own quarters.
And the temporal core?
That's going to be
a little trickier.
With Obrist's help, I'm
pretty sure I can disable it,
but not without setting off
every alarm on this ship.
We're only going
to have one chance.
It'll require precise timing.
You and me
working from within...
And Captain
Janeway
attacking from Voyager.
That is...
if the Captain's still alive.
She's alive.
Send the message.
Transmit our coordinates.
Done.
And...
give Kathryn my best.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51682.2.
I've forged a coalition
with the Nihydron,
and the Mawasi.
Together, we're preparing
to attack the weapon ship.
I've analyzed
every carrier frequency
of their transmission.
It contains a classified
Starfleet ID code
that could only have
come from Tom Paris.
It's real.
The coordinates he sent
should lead us directly
to the weapon ship.
Location?
Approximately
50 light-years from here.
Our new allies are
assembling reinforcements.
Once we're in range,
Tom says he'll try
to take the weapon ship
temporal core off-line.
When that happens,
they'll be vulnerable
to conventional weapons.
Tom will then transmit
the exact location of the core.
Our job will be
to disable the ship,
and get our people out.
Is everyone clear?
KIM: Yes, ma'am.
TORRES: Aye, Captain.
B'Elanna, Harry,
I want you to beam over
to the Nihydron vessel.
Work with
their engineers.
The entire fleet
needs to be equipped
with temporal shielding.
Aye, Captain.
Tuvok, Neelix, Seven,
you'll be working
on the Mawasi ship.
NEELIX:
Yes, Captain.
Doctor, once the attack begins,
your skills
will no doubt be required.
Join Tuvok's team.
What about yourself?
I'll be piloting Voyager,
coordinating the attack.
TORRES:
Captain,
there's barely enough
of this ship left to get there,
much less wage a war.
There's fight
in Voyager yet.
It's still got
temporal shields...
six photon torpedoes.
It'll hold together.
Besides, you know the adage,
Captain goes down
with the ship, right?
You have your orders.
Dismissed.
Tuvok, I can hear
your objections already.
I am not leaving.
Given Voyager's
damaged state,
the probability
of your surviving
an armed conflict is marginal.
Oh, I know the odds,
but I have to stay.
Voyager's done
too much for us.
Curious.
I have never understood
the human compulsion
to emotionally bond
with inanimate objects.
This vessel
has done nothing.
It is an assemblage
of bulkheads, conduits,
tritanium...
nothing more.
Oh, you're wrong.
It's much more than that.
This ship has been our home.
It's kept us together.
It's been part of our family.
As illogical as
this might sound...
I feel as close
to Voyager
as I do to any other
member of my crew.
It's carried us, Tuvok...
even nurtured us...
and right now, it
needs one of us.
I respect your decision.
Live long and prosper, Captain.
Same to you...
old friend.
Voyager to Mawasi vessel.
TUVOK:
Go ahead, Captain.
I'm picking up the weapon ship,
dead ahead.
Confirmed.
Temporal shields status.
All vessels are bringing them
on line.
This is Captain Janeway
to the fleet.
Plot an intercept course
to the weapon ship.
Sir, six vessels are
approaching our position.
Identify.
Three Nihydron warships,
two Mawasi cruisers...
and Voyager.
We're outside space-time,
impervious to their weapons.
Let them come.
I know Captain Janeway.
She wouldn't be attacking
unless she knew she
could do some damage.
( controls beeping softly )
( console beeps )
Good work, Obrist.
If she's given the other
ships temporal shielding,
they've undoubtedly
informed their homeworlds.
They'll be able to protect their
planets against your weapon.
Bring the weapon to full power.
Stand by
for multiple incursions.
We'll have to disable
their temporal shields first.
Make the necessary calculations.
TUVOK:
All vessels report ready.
Let's see if Tom
has done his part.
Janeway to the fleet.
Attack pattern omega.
Engage.
Condition?
No damage.
Temporal core is stable.
Return fire.
TUVOK:
Captain,
two Nihydron vessels
have been destroyed.
Janeway to the fleet.
Evasive pattern delta.
We're going to have to wait.
Come on, Tom.
Come on.
Target the other vessels.
Obrist...
I said target the vessels.
( equipment powering down )
( alarm blaring )
You're deactivating
the temporal core.
I'm sorry, sir.
It's over.
Get back to your stations.
You will not disobey me.
We're phasing back
into normal space-time.
Reconfigure
to conventional weapons.
( console beeping )
TUVOK:
Captain, Chakotay and Paris
were beamed aboard our vessel.
Everything's going as planned.
Tom sent me the coordinates
of their temporal core
before he left.
I'm transmitting them
to you now.
KRENIM:
Conventional weapons are on line
and fully charged, sir.
Fire at will!
( cries out )
( groans )
KRENIM:
Sir, weapons are back
to full capacity.
Target Voyager.
Put Janeway out of her misery.
TUVOK:
All our ships have
been disabled, Captain.
Do you have weapons?
Negative.
Torpedo launchers are down.
I'm setting a collision course.
Janeway to the fleet.
Take your temporal shields
off-line.
TUVOK:
Captain, we won't be protected.
Exactly.
If that ship is destroyed,
all of history
might be restored,
and this is one year
I'd like to forget.
Time's...up.
The core is
destabilizing.
It's going to cause
a temporal incursion
within the ship.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51252.3.
The past couple of weeks
have been uneventful,
but we've made
excellent progress
on the new Astrometrics Lab.
When can you
bring it on line?
SEVEN:
We just did.
KIM:
In fact, we're
in the process
of charting a
new course home.
JANEWAY:
I'd say this is cause
for celebration.
TUVOK:
A vessel is approaching
off the port bow, Captain.
On screen.
They're hailing us.
JANEWAY:
Open a channel.
You've entered Krenim space.
State your identity.
Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
We're just passing through,
trying to get home.
This region is in dispute.
I suggest
you avoid our territory.
Thanks for the warning.
Good journey.
Tom, plot a course
around Krenim space.
Aye, sir.
CHAKOTAY:
So what do you think?
How about a ground-breaking
ceremony for our new lab?
Sounds great.
I think I'll replicate
a bottle of Saint Emilion
for the occasion,
2370, I hear that
was a good year.
Good morning.
Join me
for breakfast?
In a little while.
I still have a...
few more calculations.
There are always
"a few more calculations."
It's a beautiful day.
Spend it with me.
I suppose I can
make the time.
( theme music plays )