JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51367.2.
We've spent the last three days
on the Mari homeworld.
It's been a while since
we've had the opportunity
to make new friends,
and the crew seems to be making
the most of our stay.
( majestic theme playing )
Neelix.
Tom. You've been doing
a little shopping.
It's a present
for B'Elanna.
What is it?
Well, it's sort
of personal.
Of course.
Say no more.
I'm on my way
for a little romantic
rendezvous myself.
( sniffing )
Neelix...
are you wearing
cologne?
Oh.
Talchok musk.
Very enticing scent,
don't you think?
Well, uh, it
certainly is...
musky.
I'm going
to see Talli again.
Ooh, that was fast work.
Where're you taking her?
Well, actually, I haven't
gotten that far yet.
I'm going to visit her shop,
under the pretext of buying
some produce for the ship,
and then I thought I'd just
sort of segue smoothly
into some dinner
and dancing.
Ha, ha. Sounds like
a good strategy.
You really think so?
I mean, you used to be quite
the ladies' man.
"Used to be"?
Well, I mean, you're involved
now, so, of course,
you won't be availing yourself
of all the beautiful,
fascinating
and very open-minded Mari women.
Neelix, are you trying
to depress me?
I just...
I haven't been with anyone
since Kes,
and I'm feeling a little rusty.
I could use some advice.
The best advice I can give you
is to just be yourself.
Right.
Be myself.
Actually, that's the
second-best piece of advice.
What's the first?
Go a little easier on the musk.
( soft theme playing )
( sniffing )
( crowd chattering )
I'm sorry, Mr. Guill,
but that's my final offer.
Actually, Captain,
I sense you'd be willing
to raise your price
to 300 renns.
Lieutenant Torres needs
this resonator coil to upgrade
Voyager's
communications systems.
Telepaths.
JANEWAY:
Wait a minute.
I sense you'd
be willing to...
settle for 250.
( chuckles )
You must have read my mind.
Aah! Unh. Hey!
I'm sorry.
Are you hurt?
No, no, I'm fine.
I just wish people would
look where they're going.
It's been a pleasure
doing business with you.
I'll finish up here.
Why don't you go get Neelix?
All right.
This is some
of the loveliest fruit I've--
I've seen
in a long time.
Actually, it's been
one of our worst
waterplum seasons in years.
I don't think you'll
find them very sweet.
Mmm. Mmm.
Oh, how wonderfully tart.
( chuckling )
Mmm. They'll make
excellent preserves.
Neelix?
Hmm?
Why do you want me
to tug on your whiskers?
Excu-- Excuse me?
That is what you're thinking,
isn't it?
That you'd like me
to tug on your whiskers?
Well, as a m-matter of fact...
I'd love to.
Do you have time
to wait until I close?
Yes, I think
I can rearrange my schedule.
I guess you could say
I'm becoming obsolete.
In what sense?
There's virtually no crime
left in our society.
It took many years,
but just walk
through our streets.
Look around.
Violence no longer exists.
Impressive.
I'm one of the last officers
still working
for the Constabulary.
And no doubt
one of the best.
I'm curious to know more
about your
crime-prevention methods.
Under one condition:
I want to see Voyager.
Learn about your methods.
I'm about to perform
my daily security rounds.
Join me.
They are routine
but informative.
Wonderful.
The transport
site is this way.
You prefer speaking aloud.
Why is that?
I've grown accustomed
to it over the years.
There are very few
telepaths in Starfleet.
Whatever you prefer.
Neelix.
Ready to leave?
Uh, no, uh,
you go ahead.
I haven't finished
examining the produce.
( crashing )
MALE:
Help! Help!
Somebody help me,
please!
Stop him!
( crashing and grunting )
Help me!
( suspenseful theme playing )
This will teach you
to watch
where you're
going, you idiot!
You idiot!
( groaning )
Somebody get a doctor!
Why? Why were you
beating that man?
I don't know.
( majestic theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Your "brig."
It's a puzzling concept.
Shutting someone
away as punishment.
Do you find that it
rehabilitates the prisoner?
The brig is primarily used
as a means of ensuring
the safety of others.
In what sense?
For example,
if we find ourselves
with a hostile alien
in our custody,
we may need
to confine the individual
until we can locate
the proper authorities.
I see.
And on rare occasions,
we have been forced
to incarcerate a crew member
who has committed
a serious infraction.
I'm surprised that
one of your people
could be capable of doing
something serious enough
to warrant imprisonment.
It's extremely rare.
In any case,
the brig has been occupied
for less than one percent
of our journey.
Forgive me, Tuvok,
but it seems...
barbaric.
If all species were
as enlightened
as yours and mine,
there would be no need
for prisons.
KIM ( on communicator ):
Bridge to Commander Tuvok.
Go ahead, Ensign.
Chief Examiner Nimira's
been recalled to the surface.
There's been some sort of attack
in the marketplace.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I've never seen
so much blood before.
It's all right.
I heard about someone
getting beaten once
when I was a little girl.
It's all over now.
I had nightmares
for weeks.
It's okay.
It's all right.
He was confused.
He said he didn't realize
what he'd done.
I don't understand
why nobody tried to help him.
People were shocked.
Violence is
almost unheard of here.
But when it does occur,
we like
to investigate thoroughly.
Can we help?
Yes. I would like
you, Mr. Neelix,
and, uh, Lieutenant Torres
to answer some questions.
Well, you have
our complete cooperation.
Chief Examiner,
are you suspicious
of my colleagues
for some reason?
No, Lieutenant. I'm simply
conducting an investigation.
Please.
Follow me.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Please have a seat.
I will be monitoring
your thoughts telepathically
during the interview.
This transcription device
will log your
engramatic activity,
so I can review
your statement later.
Let me get this straight.
Not only are you going
to read my mind,
you're going
to record my thoughts.
Yes.
I guess it'd be pretty tough
to keep a secret from you, hmm?
( exhales )
How long had you been
in the marketplace
when the attack occurred?
One hour--
maybe a little longer.
And exactly where
were you standing?
Directly across the square.
From where you were, did you
have a clear view of the attack?
Uh, not at first.
We just heard yelling.
Then, as we got closer,
we saw
what was happening.
What exactly brought you
to the market
in the first place?
Captain Janeway and I
had an appointment
with Mr. Guill.
For what purpose?
We'd met him the day before.
He said he could get
a spare resonator coil for us.
I see. And the two men involved
in the altercation.
Had you seen either of them
before?
I'd never seen the victim...
but the attacker...
I think he was the same man
who bumped into B'Elanna.
Bumped into her? Are you
certain?
Yes. They collided accidentally.
When exactly did
this happen?
Just as we'd settled
on the price.
He seemed to be
in quite a hurry.
Do you recall what you
were thinking at the time?
What I was thinking?
What does it matter?
Please, try to remember.
It may be important.
I didn't think about it much,
and no one was hurt,
and I was busy
trying to sort out the coins.
I'm not used
to handling currency.
What was I thinking? Ha.
I was thinking how I could bake
a delicious pie
with those waterplums.
NIMIRA:
Are you sure that's all,
Mr. Neelix?
NEELIX:
Yes, of course.
What else would
I  be thinking about?
I suppose I was
a little annoyed.
NIMIRA:
Can you be more specific?
All right.
I guess I was thinking
my foot hurt.
I mean, the idiot stepped
right on it.
Did you call him an idiot?
Of course not.
But you thought it?
I guess so.
Did you also think
about retaliating?
It was an accident.
But you said he hurt you.
It didn't occur to you
to hurt him back?
I'd never do that.
But you thought about it.
How am I supposed to remember?
Yes or no, did you think about
hurting him?
Yes or no?
Well, maybe for a split second.
Aah! Hey!
( grunting )
B'ELANNA:
I mean, he should
have been watching
where he was going,
but I realized
that he didn't do it on purpose
so I shook it off and I left.
Why?
What does it matter
what I was thinking?
Lieutenant B'Elanna Torres,
you are under arrest.
On what charge?
Aggravated violent thought
resulting in grave bodily harm.
Are you saying it's a crime
to think about violence?
Yes.
That's ridiculous.
I assure you, it's
quite necessary.
We were once a society
plagued by violence.
When we prohibited
hostile thought,
crime began to drop
immediately.
Over the past three generations,
it's all but disappeared.
So you believe
that it's all right
to tell people what they
can and cannot think?
It's an irrefutable fact
that violent thoughts
from others
can lead to violent actions.
Even if B'Elanna had
a violent thought,
it was Frane who
attacked that man.
Which he only did because he
telepathically
received that thought
from B'Elanna.
His mind was contaminated
by the image,
and it resulted in
a loss of control.
He may have committed
the physical act,
but it was instigated by you.
Where we come from,
people are responsible
for their own actions.
And here,
people are responsible
for their own thoughts.
I'm sure you can understand
how that's necessary for a race
of telepaths.
Yes, I can.
Captain!
I'll accept
that your people
can be influenced by
the thoughts of others,
but there were dozens
of people in that square.
How can you be certain
it came from B'Elanna?
The Mari no longer have
violent thoughts.
It's unlikely
any of them
could have been
responsible.
Besides, the evidence
against B'Elanna is clear.
She thought about
committing a hostile act.
I'd like to review
that evidence myself,
if you don't mind.
Certainly.
( device beeping )
But I'm afraid
you'll be disappointed.
What happens to B'Elanna now?
We have an enlightened
penal system here.
Unlike some, we don't lock
people away to punish them.
You'll be released.
Once you've undergone
the engramatic purge.
The what?
It's a medical procedure that
will identify and remove
the offending images
from your mind.
Captain!
Once identified, the images can
be removed
from Frane's mind as well.
Memory extraction.
That's a dangerous
procedure.
There is a risk
of neurological damage,
but it's necessary
for us to treat Frane.
( beeps )
Will you at least
delay the procedure
until we've had a chance
to review the evidence?
Will you?
It'll take us about a day
to reconfigure our instruments.
That's all the time
I can give you.
I'll need.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( computers beeping )
Captain, we've got to get
B'Elanna out of there.
You know the rules, Tom.
We can't pick and choose
which laws we'll respect
and which we won't.
Nobody can be expected
to control their thoughts.
Tell that to the Mari.
Are you just gonna
let them
put her through
this process?
I'm doing everything
I can to stop it.
Neelix is going to file
a diplomatic protest,
and Tuvok and I
will be going over
the witness statements.
Maybe we can poke
a few holes
in the Chief
Examiner's case.
And if you can't?
( sighs )
Then let's hope
the doctor can figure out
how to reverse
an engramatic purge.
( computer beeping )
All away personnel
have been notified
to return to the ship
as soon as possible.
So much for R&amp;R.
Chakotay, we've
got to talk.
Have a seat.
Here?
I'm sure the Captain
wouldn't object.
What's on your mind?
While Tuvok
and the Captain
are reviewing
the evidence,
B'Elanna's sitting
in a Mari jail cell waiting
for some sort of lobotomy.
We can't let that happen.
What did you
have in mind?
Break her out.
And risk an all-out
confrontation with the Mari?
They're a bunch of pacifists.
They're no match for us.
You're probably right,
but before we start resorting
to extreme measures,
don't you think we should give
the Captain a chance
to find a legal solution?
By the time that happens,
it may be too late.
I'll tell you what.
Why don't you come up
with a rescue plan--
one that minimizes
the possibility
of violence,
and I'll review it.
You're just trying
to keep me busy, aren't you?
Can you blame me?
I'm serious about this,
Chakotay.
So am I.
If your plan is sound,
and the Captain doesn't have
any luck on her end,
I'll recommend we attempt
the rescue.
Thanks. I'll
get right on it.
Tom, I may have let you sit
in the Captain's chair,
but remember,
she's still the boss.
Then you don't accept
the Chief Examiner's
conclusion?
I'm not dismissing it,
but I'm not going
to accept it blindly either.
I've spent
a great deal of time
with Nimira over
the past few days.
She clearly is
a very skilled investigator.
I'm sure she is.
And this isn't
the first time
Lieutenant Torres'
violent proclivities
have created problems.
No argument there.
But I have
a hard time buying
that one fleeting thought
makes her responsible
for a vicious attack.
From what I've learned,
crime here is a result
of exposure
to violent thought,
much as it was on Vulcan
before my people learned
to control their emotions.
In my opinion,
the Mari should be
applauded
for their efforts.
Oh, I'm sure their intentions
are admirable, but, uh...
I'm not about to let them
scramble B'Elanna's brain
without a fight.
But we must prepare ourselves
for the probability
that she will turn out
to be culpable
for the crime.
Maybe so...
and then again...
maybe not.
Take a look at this.
I don't mean to accuse
your friend Nimira
of being less than
thorough, Tuvok, but...
don't you find that
just the least bit curious?
"New evidence"?
( computer beeping )
It concerns the attacker,
Mr. Frane.
According to your own
security records,
he was arrested
on four previous occasions
for harboring
violent thoughts.
You classified him
as an "habitual perpetrator
of hostile images."
True.
But those thoughts
were purged each time.
He spent years
in neurogenic restructuring.
The records also
say he was cured.
Still, it is possible
that Frane had
a relapse...
that he alone
is responsible
for his actions
at the marketplace.
Possible, but unlikely.
Our engramatic
scans of Frane
show that Lieutenant
Torres's thought
was prevalent in his
mind during the attack.
And you are certain
no other violent
thoughts were present?
I'm beginning to feel
like I'm the one
being investigated.
I am simply exploring
all logical options.
As a fellow
law enforcement officer,
you should
understand that.
I do.
And I'm willing to share
my findings with you.
But if you're
trying to prove
your crewmate's innocence,
you're too late.
The case is closed.
Do you think
that this is easy for me?
I don't want to harm B'Elanna,
but I don't have a choice.
That thought has
to be contained.
Otherwise, we risk
further violence, maybe even
a citywide panic.
You told me your people
spent centuries
learning how to control
their violent impulses.
I know we haven't achieved
your level of discipline,
but we're trying.
I thought you'd understand.
I am not judging
your culture.
In fact, I admire it.
I have enjoyed
your company in particular,
but I cannot abandon
my responsibility
to B'Elanna.
I must continue
my own investigation.
Go right ahead.
But I intend to proceed
with the engramatic purge.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Telepathy...
I don't like it.
Never have.
It's bad
for negotiations,
it's bad
for relationships,
and it's certainly
been bad for B'Elanna.
The fault was her own.
What are you
talking about?
She was careless
with her thoughts.
The result
was violence.
B'Elanna's not used
to being around telepaths.
That doesn't make
her guilty.
Then her crime
was ignorance.
A common affliction
among your crew.
What's that supposed to mean?
You make contact
with alien species
without sufficient understanding
of their nature.
As a result, Voyager's directive
to "seek out new civilizations"
often ends in conflict.
What you call "ignorance,"
we call "exploration."
And sometimes it means
taking a few risks.
But it's certainly better
than assimilating
everything in your path.
Your goal is to share knowledge.
Assimilation is the perfect
means of attaining that goal.
"Perfect."
Good morning,
Miss Tembit.
Your usual selection?
Yes, please.
Okay. Oh, I'm--
I'm so sorry.
Aah! Hey!
Idiot! Watch what
you're doing!
( grunts )
( Talli screams )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( crowd chattering )
She's dead.
I can't believe
she's dead.
I know this is difficult
for you, Mr. Neelix,
but try to recount for me
everything that happened.
Seven and I
were packing
to return to the ship.
We heard a scream.
I went running...
The old lady was just
standing over Talli's body,
holding the bloody
knife in her hand.
I didn't even get
a chance to say good-bye.
Did the old woman
say anything?
Not that I remember.
She was as shocked and
confused as anyone else.
Do you think this
is somehow connected
with the other attack?
I'm not certain,
but it strikes me
as more than coincidence
that two violent altercations
have occurred within two days,
in a city which purports
to have eliminated
virtually all crime.
MAN ( on communicator ):
Bridge to Commander Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
Chief Examiner Nimira
wants to see you.
She's requesting permission
to transport aboard.
Permission granted.
Have her escorted
to the briefing room.
Tuvok out.
We will continue later.
Commander.
She was a wonderful young woman.
Whoever's responsible
for her death. Find them,
and see that they're
brought to justice.
I will do my best, Mr. Neelix.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( door closes )
Thanks for seeing me.
I heard what happened.
Do you have any idea
what caused
this latest attack?
I just finished interviewing
the old woman.
And?
She attacked the victim
in response to the same
violent thought
that motivated
the previous beating.
B'Elanna's thought?
But both she and Frane
are in custody.
How could the thought
have been passed to anyone else?
I don't know.
That's why I'm here.
I need your help.
Then you shall have it.
Thank you.
I don't know
why that thought
is still
contaminating people,
but I have got
to put a stop to it.
I've never dealt
with a murder before,
but you've had experience
with homicide
investigations?
I have.
I thought I would
start by tracing
the old woman's whereabouts
for the past few days
to see where she might have
encountered the thought.
A wise choice.
In the meantime,
I would like
to interview B'Elanna
more extensively.
Perhaps a fresh
perspective
might uncover facts
you hadn't considered.
I'll arrange it immediately.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I'm not sure I like
the idea of a mind-meld
any better
than an engramatic purge.
It will be
a limited meld.
I will focus exclusively
on your memories
of the events
surrounding the crime.
It poses no danger.
Are you ready?
Your mind to my mind.
Your thoughts
to my thoughts.
Recall your encounter
with Mr. Frane.
He bumped into you.
What happened next?
B'ELANNA:
I guess that's when
I had the thought
about hitting him.
TUVOK:
And after that?
B'ELANNA:
Guill came over
and asked if I was hurt.
TUVOK:
And what were you
thinking at that moment?
Why?
I'm sensing something
more to the encounter
than what you've told me.
Try to recall.
It may be important.
Well, he was just holding me
by the shoulders.
TUVOK:
You said he'd been
reading your mind
during the negotiation.
Was he still doing it?
B'ELANNA:
I don't know.
You experienced
negative feelings about him.
( suspenseful theme playing )
He gave me the creeps.
In what sense?
He, uh, wanted something.
Something terrible.
What the hell?
( gasps )
Why didn't
I remember that before?
You may be recalling
an unconscious thought
you had at the time
or an intuition.
Perhaps I should
ask Mr. Guill.
Mr. Guill.
I'm Commander Tuvok,
Voyager's Chief of Security.
My children get upset
when I'm late for supper.
If you're here
to do business,
we could make an appointment
for tomorrow.
I'm here to talk to you
about the attack.
Why me?
My crewmate, Lieutenant Torres
has been charged
with the crime.
I believe
you're acquainted with her.
Lieutenant Torres, yes.
She was arrested?
The Chief Examiner believes
it was her violent thought,
which prompted
the beating.
She seemed like such
a pleasant young woman.
Apparently, she was
almost knocked over
while doing
business with you.
Do you recall that?
Yes.
A man accidentally
ran into her and...
You're not like the others
from your ship, are you?
You're a telepath.
That is correct.
Why are you so curious
about what happened?
I am conducting my own
investigation of the crime.
I see.
For a moment, I thought you had
another reason for asking.
You...struggle
with violent thoughts as well.
Terrible images,
but they're hidden
deep within your mind.
I am in control
of those images.
All members of the Vulcan race
learn to inhibit emotions.
If my unconscious thoughts
are disturbing you,
I will attempt to suppress
them further.
No, please.
Don't trouble yourself.
I can't see them clearly enough
to be affected.
I sense that you are fascinated
with my unconscious thoughts.
That you would like to see
more of them if you could.
No.
I was just thinking
maybe I could help you.
Help me?
In learning how to deal
with these...
dark impulses.
No, thank you.
I have sufficient means
of controlling them.
I'm sure you do.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Any other questions?
No.
Then, if you'll excuse me,
I really can't be late
for the table.
Do you have the money?
3,000 renns.
I have something
exciting for you tonight.
Why are you
following us?
I was thinking
about what you said...
your interest
in my unconscious thoughts.
Perhaps we could
help each other.
How would we do that?
By telepathically exchanging
violent images.
That is what
you want, isn't it?
To see what's buried
in my unconscious?
Who is he?
Quiet.
Why should I trust you?
Because you know
we are very much alike.
Perhaps I was mistaken.
Wait.
Maybe we can
be of use to each other.
But you'll have
to get rid of this.
( combadge clatters
to ground )
Come back later,
Malin.
If I'm right,
I'll have thoughts to share
that are darker
than anything you can imagine.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( voices screaming )
( barking )
( both gasping )
Well?
Fascinating.
Now...
show me.
I'll need a few
moments to recover.
I'm surprised
you're so easily tired.
Your telepathic abilities
are strong.
It is not often that
I exercise those skills.
There must be violent thoughts
to be had from your shipmates,
whether they want
to share them or not.
After all, they
couldn't stop a telepath
from probing their minds,
could they?
Is that how you acquire
your merchandise?
Sometimes I buy.
Sometimes I find
a person like you
who's willing to share,
and, yes, when the opportunity
presents itself,
I take what I need.
Which is what you did
to Lieutenant Torres.
Frane took her thought,
not me.
So, you know Mr. Frane.
Only casually.
Well enough
to be in business with him?
Why do you ask?
I am interested in the thought
he acquired from B'Elanna.
Her violent tendencies
have always fascinated me,
yet I've never succeeded
in probing her mind.
If you could help me purchase
that thought...
It's impossible.
Frane's already
had it purged.
Odd.
I was certain
you possessed it.
Me?
Didn't you extract the thought
from B'Elanna as well,
just after she
collided with Frane?
What?
I reevaluated B'Elanna's
memories of the incident.
She remembers that
you probed her mind.
She remembers
incorrectly.
Perhaps...
or perhaps you did
extract that image,
which would explain
why that same thought
is still in circulation.
Why it prompted
a murder this morning.
Enough!
It's time you gave me
what you promised.
The only person you'll be
sharing thoughts with tonight
is the Chief Examiner.
Where are you going?
Stand aside.
Tuvok's taking
me into custody.
No!
( all grunting )
( dramatic theme calming )
( computer beeping negative )
Still no sign of him.
Try a multiphasic bio-scan.
We're being hailed, Captain.
It's Nimira.
On screen.
Chief Examiner, have you
had any luck locating Tuvok?
I'm afraid not.
I'd like to send a search party.
I can't allow that.
Why not?
We can't risk further
violations of our laws.
That's ridiculous.
Tom.
I really don't think
we pose
a serious threat.
There's nothing more
to discuss.
Lieutenant Torres
will be purged
then returned to you.
Oh. Captain, you can't
let them do that.
The decision's been made.
I'm sorry.
( computer beeps )
( sighs )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( grunting and gasping )
Let go of me!
B'Elanna, please.
Try to relax.
Oh, you have got
to be kidding!
Sedate her.
No. Wait!
( gasping )
Proceed.
You won't escape punishment
for your crimes.
Quiet!
( panting )
You are responsible
for a death.
I never meant
that to happen.
The old woman begged me for
that thought. I had to help her.
Here.
( grunts )
You are justifying murder.
Enough.
Malin, hold him still.
Now...
show me.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( all screaming )
( roaring )
You're holding back.
I haven't seen
the best of it yet, have I?
No.
Then show me.
( gasps )
If I show you,
will you let me go?
Yes.
Come closer.
( both grunting )
Don't be alarmed.
This will
allow you to see
the deepest recesses
of my mind.
My mind...to your mind
and my thoughts...
to your thoughts.
Yes.
Good.
( suspenseful theme playing )
This is the side of you
I wanted to know.
( gasping )
( grunting )
What's...happening?
We are locked
in a Vulcan mind-meld.
You don't understand
the truth of violence.
( groans )
Its darkness...
its power!
( whimpering )
( groaning )
( sputtering )
Please. Stop.
Increase the electrochemical
displacement,
but be very careful
with the synaptic potentials.
One miscalculation
and we could permanently damage
her cerebral cortex.
MARI ( on communicator ):
Communications Center
to Chief Examiner Nimira.
Nimira.
Captain Janeway insists
on speaking with you.
She says it's extremely urgent.
Relay her signal.
What is it, Captain?
JANEWAY ( on communicator ):
It's imperative that
you discontinue
Lieutenant Torres' engramatic
extraction immediately.
Commander Tuvok
has found new evidence,
which proves her innocence.
( majestic theme playing )
( door opens )
I hope this interruption
is justified.
Suspending an engramatic purge
once it's begun
is highly irregular.
Then let's not waste
any more time. Commander.
I have discovered
that Guill and Frane
are responsible
for the beating
in the marketplace,
and consequently,
for Talli's murder.
Guill, the merchant?
That is correct.
What possible involvement
could he have?
It was Frane who acted
on the violent thought.
That is not in dispute.
However,
Lieutenant Torres' thought
was not transferred
accidentally.
I don't understand.
When Guill first met
Lieutenant Torres,
he sensed strong, violent
tendencies within her,
a potential
for mental imagery
which interested him.
In order to exploit
that potential,
he conspired with Frane
to provoke B'Elanna.
They wanted to trigger
a violent thought,
so they could telepathically
draw it from her mind.
I can't believe that.
It is precisely
what happened.
Unfortunately,
they underestimated
the intensity of the thought.
It was more powerful
than anything either of
them had ever experienced.
As a result,
Frane lost control
and attacked
the victim.
Why would peaceful men
like Guill and Frane
want to subject themselves
to such hostile images?
My investigation has uncovered
a rather disturbing side
of Mari society.
A black market,
if you will,
in which many
of your citizens
trade in illicit
mental imagery.
Guill is a very prominent figure
in this underground,
or was, until I brought him
into custody.
Why would any of my people
want to indulge
in that kind of behavior?
Apparently, outlawing
violent thought
hasn't made it go away.
All you've done
is force people
to share it
in back alleys.
TUVOK:
It seems you have
a somewhat more...
serious problem than the random
thoughts of a single alien.
Even if I believed you,
I'm not sure anyone else would.
Then I suggest you interrogate
Guill yourselves.
His engramatic record
will undoubtedly confirm
what I've told you.
Where is he now?
We have him confined.
In our brig.
( soft theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Chief Examiner Nimira has
taken custody of Mr. Guill.
Whether his arrest
will lead to reforms
in the Mari justice system
is anyone's guess.
In the meantime, the doctor
is treating Lieutenant Torres
and Commander Tuvok.
Fortunately, the Mari
didn't get very far
with the procedure.
You can return to duty,
Lieutenant,
though perhaps with one
or two fewer violent engrams
in that fiery head
of yours.
It's all right, Doc.
There are plenty more
where those came from.
Duly warned.
Thanks for getting me
out of there.
I was merely
pursuing the truth.
Ah. So if
I was responsible
for passing that thought,
you would have let them
lobotomize me?
It is incumbent upon us
to respect the laws
of the societies
we visit.
Ah. So...
you still a fan
of the Mari legal system?
My views have been
somewhat modified.
Then you're not
going to lecture me
about losing my temper?
If you must know,
investigating this case
has given me a new respect
for your inner struggle.
Really?
Burdened as you are
by your primitive
Klingon psyche,
it is a wonder
you are able to keep
your violent thoughts
under control
as much as you do.
Thanks...I think.
You're welcome.
Of course, there are
various Vulcan techniques
which could help you
increase your self-control.
You don't say.
( soft theme playing )
( computer beeping )
( gasps )
Come in.
I must speak with you.
Of course.
Have a seat.
I prefer to stand.
I keep forgetting.
You once encouraged me
to express my opinions
if I had something
relevant to say.
Go right ahead.
You wish to return this vessel
to the Alpha Quadrant,
and yet you are following
Starfleet protocol
regarding first contact.
The two objectives
are incompatible.
How so?
Your philosophy of exploration
exposes Voyager
to constant risk.
If you maintain
a direct course,
to Earth and avoid
all extraneous contact
with alien species,
it will increase
your chances of survival.
Well, that would make
a dull ride home.
Captain?
We seek out new races
because we want to,
not because we're
following protocols.
We have an insatiable curiosity
about the universe.
Your Chief Engineer and Security
Officer were nearly lost today.
That is unacceptable.
To you, maybe,
but not to me or my crew.
Our experience with the Mari
gave us an insight
into a culture
we've never encountered.
But that is irrelevant.
No.
It's how we gain knowledge.
Then we are in disagreement.
Good. I dread the day
when everyone on this ship
agrees with me.
I thank you for your opinion,
but our mission
is not going to change.
( soft theme playing )
Dismissed.
( majestic theme playing )