( crowd yelling )
Animali!
Bruti animali!
WOMAN:
No, Leonardo,
you are the animal!
MAN:
A bird who cannot fly!
Better than a man
who cannot think!
WOMAN:
The pigeon speaks!
( people cooing )
( growling )
Maestro!
Stupido!
Foolish Florentines!
A bird is
a mechanical instrument
that works according
to mathematical laws.
An instrument that surely
I can recreate.
How did it fail?
Maybe you underestimated
the wingspan.
Had not the River Arno
taken us to its arms,
we would both
have died.
Jumping off the bridge
was a wise precaution.
Against death, yes.
Against humiliation...no.
"The great bird
will take flight,
and bring glory
to its nest."
So I have bragged for months.
Instead, we almost drown
with half of Florence watching.
( grunts )
Finito!
No more.
Catarina...
have you been to France?
Not recently.
Ah. The king of France
is a great admirer of mine.
"The divine Leonardo"
is all I hear
when I walk through
his streets.
And what music do I find
in the streets of Florence, eh?
The cooing of pigeons
and the babbling of fools.
Catarina,
we are leaving.
You're giving up.
Hmm?
Again.
Your beautiful painting
of the Adoration...
the great
bronze horse
in Milan...
the Battle of Anghiari...
unfinished, all of them.
You were going to publish
your notebooks.
You never did.
You have given up,
abandoned your most
important works.
Why?
There is a...
a tavern just outside Paris,
Catarina,
a charming bistro
where the wine is...
Terramotto.
Janeway to the Bridge.
CHAKOTAY:
We're under attack, Captain.
I'm on my way.
( horses whinny, people scream )
Earthquakes...and idiots.
Florence be damned.
Who are they and why
are they shooting at us?
Unknown, Captain.
They're not responding
to hails.
Damage?
TUVOK: None.
KIM:
I'm reading a slight
destabilization
along the shield perimeter.
Attempting
to compensate.
Uh, Torres to the Bridge.
JANEWAY: Go ahead.
We just lost
the warp diagnostic assembly.
What do you mean "lost"?
It disappeared.
I'm picking up
dematerializations on Decks 4
through 12.
Evasive maneuvers.
They're matching
our course changes.
It's definitely some kind
of transporter beam.
Fire at will.
TUVOK:
I have the will,
but not the means, Captain.
Targeting control is down.
Why?
KIM:
Captain, the main
computer processor is gone.
We've lost weapons, navigation
and propulsion.
Backup systems
are coming on line.
Full phasers,
manual targeting,
keep firing
until you hit something.
The other ships are retreating.
Chakotay
to all decks.
Full damage reports.
I feel like
we've just been mugged.
They were employing
a high-energy transporter beam,
designed to locate objects
of technological value
and remove them.
They removed a lot.
Five tricorders,
three phaser rifles,
a couple of photon
torpedo casings,
two antimatter
injectors,
a month's supply
of emergency rations.
No great loss there.
DOCTOR:
Excuse me.
You're forgetting
the most important thing
of all, my mobile emitter.
Without it,
I'm stuck in Sick Bay.
I can't go anywhere.
We'll do
the best we can, Doctor,
but our top priority
is the main
computer processor.
B'Elanna, I want a defense
against another
transporter attack.
Harry, do everything you can
to track
those ships.
Yes, ma'am.
Dismissed.
( console beeping )
( door opens )
Seven...hey...
If you're here
to fraternize,
I do not have
the time.
Actually, the Captain
wanted me to locate
the ships
that attacked us.
I've pushed
the long-range sensors
about as far
as they'll go...
And now you believe the
sensors can be extended
by using the deep space
imaging system.
Well, yes.
I've been working
on that exact procedure
for the past two hours.
Really?
Let's have a look.
Do you doubt my ability
to finish the task?
It...
Look...
I came here to work.
Um...I realized you'd
already started the job...
so I offered to help.
That's all.
I offered to help.
An algorithmic feedback
is interfering
with the resolution.
Decompile data banks
59 through 17
and attempt
to isolate it.
Now...
or you should leave.
Okay.
I'm a pretty
easygoing person.
I mean, it takes
a lot to...
ruffle my...
feathers.
( clears throat )
But that's not
true of everybody.
You've got to learn
how to phrase things
a little more...
diplomatically.
Or not.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51386.4.
With ship's systems
at nearly half capacity,
it's taken us ten days
to track our stolen technology.
I'm picking up
Starfleet signatures
from two of the continents.
Can you find the main
computer processor?
It's on the northern
continent...
in what looks
like a city...
but there's a lot
of signal interference.
I'll never be able to
localize it from here.
TUVOK:
Captain, I've identified
nearly 27 kinds of alien ships
in orbit of this planet.
It appears to be an active
center of commerce.
We should be able to place
an undercover away team
on either continent
without attracting attention.
That's good enough for now.
Tuvok, you and I
are going after the processor.
Tom, Neelix, I want you
on the other continent,
find out what you can.
At the very least, try to get
our emergency rations back.
Chakotay, you have the Bridge.
( conversing in alien language )
It never fails
to impress me.
No matter how vast
the differences
may be between cultures,
people always have something
that somebody else wants
and trade is born.
Or more to the point,
theft.
What have you got?
The materials in the
construction of this city,
and the technology in use,
appear to have originated
from numerous sources.
No doubt stolen.
The myriad signatures
have resulted
in high interference levels.
I am unable to...
A moment.
I am picking up
a Starfleet signature.
The computer
processor?
I don't believe so.
The signal magnitude
is too low.
The signature is...
approaching.
DA VINCI:
Catarina!
Che maraviglia!
Out of my way!
Scusa.
Perdono.
Catarina!
Welcome!
Welcome to America!
Tell me, Catarina,
what do you think
of the New World?
How did you get here?
A question I have
asked myself many times.
One moment, I was packing
for my journey to France,
the next, I was in
this land of marvels.
Possibly, upon leaving
my workshop,
I was accosted
by Spanish sailors...
rendered unconscious,
delivered to a galleon
in the port
of Genoa and carried
like a sack of grain
across the vast Atlantic.
Curious ears.
My traveling companion,
Tuvok.
Oh, what the old
philosophers say is true,
"monstrous and wonderful
are the peoples
of undiscovered lands."
But tell me,
Catarina...
how did you come
to the Americas?
Oh, it's a long story.
A Portuguese ship,
some Turkish pirates...
a couple of hurricanes...
I'll tell you all about
it some other time.
Excuse me.
There is the man that I
have been looking for.
He has an apparatus that
I need for my next invention.
My patron is
a demanding taskmaster.
Your patron?
The prince
of this city.
Buon giorno, signori.
The da Vinci character
is interpreting this world
through the limited capacity
of his holodeck program.
He sees everything
in 16th century terms.
But what is
he doing here?
I was running
the da Vinci simulation
when we were attacked.
His program must have been
active in the computer's memory
when the processor
was beamed off the ship.
And then downloaded into the
Doctor's mobile emitter.
But by whom?
His patron?
The prince?
Marvelous, no?
A plasma injector
conduit.
Starfleet issue.
Call it
what you will.
With this machine,
I can make
mercury flow
in three directions at once.
You must see my new workshop.
The prince has been
very supportive.
Andiamo.
Let's go.
So, Catarina...
what do you think of this place?
My workshop in Florence
was but a cave of ignorance
in comparison.
Your new patron
gave you all this?
He is the perfect prince.
Intelligent, but
not overly so.
In awe of my talent,
but not threatened by it.
And above all,
and most importantly,
his purse
is inexhaustible.
And in return for
all this support?
I give him my ideas.
I have even resurrected
my great bird,
like the phoenix
of legend.
They have materials
here, Catarina,
that are so strong
and so light,
that surely my prototype
will ascend to the heavens.
Be careful!
They have found a way
to harness the energy
of a thunderstorm,
and to expel it
with great force.
A pistole
that shoots
not a lead ball,
but a bolt
of lightning.
Well, I'd like to meet
this patron of yours.
And so you shall
this very evening.
But I caution you...
he is as ruthless as a Borgia.
CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 51392.7.
Though we've yet to hear
from the Captain and Tuvok,
Paris and Neelix have returned
from their mission
to the southern continent
with some disturbing evidence.
Who sold you
these things?
I didn't come here
to be interrogated.
You told me you had
a warp coil to trade.
I said you could
talk
with Commander Chakotay.
I didn't say he'd necessarily
do business with you.
Well, this is
a waste of my time.
I agree.
There's the door.
What?
Goodbye.
Make sure he doesn't get lost on
the way out.
No, wait, wait.
His name is Tau.
He controls the Seventh
Province of the North.
He sells weapons
and technology.
Yes.
Which he confiscates
from passing ships.
Yes, using
his translocator device.
Which he
also stole.
It's made him a rich man.
There are a few items
I'd like to get back.
Where can I find him?
I deal with a go-between.
I've answered
enough of your questions.
Let's talk about
that warp coil.
I'm looking
for something--
You can keep what you've got.
We'll call it even.
This was a waste
of my time.
Not really.
These colors
look good on you.
Torpedoes,
plasma grenades...
particle beam rifles...
I can even get
a ceremonial spear
if you're interested.
I am not interested.
My point is, no matter
what the weaponry,
if you desire it,
chances are I have it.
Or I can get it.
Your prices are said
to be unreasonable.
"Unreasonable" is
such a strong term.
But if I can't
sell to you,
I'll sell to one
of the other colonies
in your system.
A violent sort,
your neighbors,
aren't they?
I'd hate to make
your life difficult
by offering my
weapons to them.
But if you don't
give me a choice...
There can be no doubt
our computer processor
is not in the city.
Well, that certainly
makes things
a little more
difficult.
Leonardo's new patron.
He's quite
the businessman.
We may have no choice
but to do business with him.
DA VINCI:
Catarina!
Here are some friends
I want you to meet.
Try to keep
our hologram occupied.
TUVOK:
But, Captain...
Well make small talk.
Vulcans do not make small talk.
Improvise.
Thank you.
That is very considerate.
Catarina,
wait a minute!
Mr. Da Vinci,
how have you been?
Benissimo. Now if
you will pardon me.
I wish to speak
with you.
What about?
About you.
You are most intriguing.
Ah, grazie.
And you, Signore Tuvok,
are equally provocative.
Where, exactly,
are you from?
Scandinavia.
So...what do the
Scandinavians think
of this New World?
It is...fascinating.
And you are
obviously enjoying it.
Beyond words.
Yes.
Italy is already
a fading memory.
This city is full
of mechanical marvels,
the countryside
alive with creatures
strange and wonderful.
I'm curious.
How have you spent
your time here?
I work...on my
inventions and my art,
and I accompany
the prince
when he goes to visit
his great fortresses.
Well, this fascinating
conversation...
has left me as dry as Vulcan.
Vulcan?
An island off Sicily.
Have you been there?
No.
Pity.
We'll talk later.
Good evening.
And to you.
Enjoying yourself?
Not yet.
No?
How can I change that?
By having exactly what I want,
and selling it to me
at a low price.
The former's quite likely,
but as for the latter,
I don't sell
inexpensive merchandise.
I have a client
who runs a colony
about 20 parsecs from here.
His computer is outmoded,
so I'm...looking
for a replacement.
A computer that could coordinate
the systems of an entire colony.
That's no small order.
But I think
I might have something
that will interest you.
Hello, Computer,
and how are you today?
COMPUTER:
All systems are functioning
within normal parameters.
Verbal interface.
Impressive.
Computer, tell us your
technical specifications.
Simultaneous access
to 47 million data channels,
transluminal processing
at 575 trillion calculations
per nanosecond.
Interested?
Operational temperature margins
from ten degrees Kelvin
to 1,790 degrees Kelvin.
I could sell it to you,
but I could hardly let it go
for anything less than...
a warship.
Or we could find something else
in your price range.
JANEWAY:
We should be looking
for a stronghold
or storage facility,
anyplace Tau might keep
the stolen technology.
There are
several possibilities,
all within a ten-kilometer
radius of the city.
I must admit, your Mr. da Vinci
is an astute observer of nature.
These maps
couldn't be improved upon
by Voyager's
topographical computer.
He was a Renaissance man, Tuvok.
Interpreted, reinterpreted,
deconstructed, fantasized about
all through history.
Vasari thought he was an angel.
Freud thought he had
a problem
with his mother.
James T. Kirk
claimed he met him,
although the evidence
is less than conclusive.
DA VINCI:
Buon giorno, amici.
Good morning, Maestro.
Did you sleep well?
Too well, I'm afraid.
My apologies, Catarina.
The morning is half gone.
Nevertheless, the images
that come before the eyes
upon awakening
can be inspiring.
( chuckling )
Indeed.
Catarina, where did I leave
my silver-tip pen?
I could swear
it was here on the--
Captain, we should
return to Voyager.
With my tricorder readings
and Leonardo's maps,
we can use the ship's sensors
to triangulate
the exact location
of our processor.
We'll work
on two fronts.
You go back to the ship.
I'll stay on the surface and
keep working with Leonardo.
He has access to Tau,
and he knows
the territory.
Inadvisable.
Charming as your
childhood hero may be,
the program was not designed
for use outside the holodeck.
This is Leonardo da Vinci
we're talking about.
Simulation or not,
he's one of the greatest
creative minds
in Earth's history.
The program reproduces
the entire range
of da Vinci's behavior,
his genius,
and his notorious
unreliability.
We have an
opportunity here...
and I want
to take advantage of it.
Tuvok to Voyager.
One to beam up.
...table.
Where did he go?
Back to the ship.
The ship?
You mean, the Portuguese
are still in the harbor?
Well...not exactly...
but they're nearby.
Ah.
Mad sea dogs, the Portuguese.
So, what's new?
New?
What's been happening
on the ship?
Nothing of consequence.
The Captain and Tuvok
are still searching
for the processor.
What's the mood?
If you're referring
to the crew morale,
they seem focused
on their mission.
Hmm. I heard there was
something of a fuss
in the Mess Hall
last night.
A trivial
misunderstanding.
Oh?
Well, you seem
in excellent health.
Most of your implants
are stable,
but your optical interface
is misaligned again.
I told you to come in
for maintenance once a week.
So...what happened
in the Mess Hall?
Lieutenant Torres
and I were working
on some astrometric data.
There was
a disagreement.
I understand things got
a little...heated.
Lieutenant Torres
became emotional.
She chose to
display hostility
rather than to counter
my argument.
What did she say exactly?
It is irrelevant.
Suffice it to say,
I was correct.
She was not.
Details, Seven,
I want specifics.
I see no reason
to discuss
these trivialities.
Without my mobile emitter,
I am a prisoner in here.
I need to know
what is going on
beyond these walls,
trivial or not.
( sighing )
Torres referred to me
as an automaton.
She also employed
a series of profane
Klingon insults.
Shall I translate
them for you?
By all means.
I very much--
TUVOK:
Tuvok to Seven of Nine.
Report to the Astrometrics Lab.
You may go.
I'll be right
there, Commander.
Come back whenever you feel
like talking.
I'll be right here...
all by myself.
I am entering
Leonardo's maps,
and my tricorder data
into the imaging system.
I will create
a search pattern
for our missing processor.
Da Vinci has
accurately rendered
the topographical detail.
However, his coordinate
axes are pre-Cartesian.
You will have
to convert them.
Understood.
It is puzzling that even
a Vulcan would refer
to a holographic character
by name, as if it were alive.
It seems somehow...illogical.
Localizing grid.
Altitude,
20 kilometers.
One of these
storage facilities
undoubtedly contains
the processor.
Increase sensor resolution
to maximum and scan the area.
There.
Our computer processor
is inside this structure.
Unfortunately, the building
is surrounded
by a dispersion field.
Transport will be impossible.
If the captain can get
inside the facility
and reach the processor itself,
she may be able to assist us.
If she were to initiate
a power surge in the processor,
it might produce a signal strong
enough for us to lock onto.
That is what I
was referring to.
I will inform
the captain.
It's not too far,
across open country.
Leonardo says he's been there,
and he can help me get inside.
TUVOK:
Understood.
Stand by for my signal.
If I can find the processor,
be prepared
to beam it back to Voyager.
Aye, Captain.
Tuvok out.
So it's Captain?
I see you and my hologram
are old friends.
My engineers have
developed a defense
against
your transporter,
so I suggest you return
what you took from us,
and let me go.
Or what?
You're in no position
to bargain.
The only ones who will
bargain will be your crew
and it'll cost them
a great deal to get
their Captain back.
I wonder what you're
worth to them...
( groans )
He'll be fine.
Let's move.
I'm not going.
You said
you'd help me.
I have already
gone too far.
He was threatening you,
I had no alternative.
But I must be here when
he recovers his senses.
I will try to explain.
Maybe, if I am lucky,
he will not have me executed.
We are leaving.
Your time here is over.
I will not leave
this New World!
Your New World
is a prison.
You are under
his control.
When are we not
in prison?
Hmm?
When are our lives free
from the influence
of those who have
more power than us?
If this New World is a cage,
than it is a cage of gold,
of marvels...
of opportunities.
If this prince is violent,
violence can be tempered.
But you can't stay
here forever, Leonardo.
Europe is your home.
Europe is despicable.
Here I am free to do
what I wish,
free from judgment,
free to fail,
without a sense
of shame, without...
without the taunts
of the ignorant.
Leonardo, whether you want
to admit it or not,
they do need you back home.
In Florence, Milan, Avignon,
they need your genius,
they need your heart,
and right now
I need you too.
So come on.
I will not go...
for Florence or Milan
or Avignon...
but for you, Catarina...
for you, I will go.
I've lost the Captain's
combadge signature.
Scan for the holo-emitter.
It's 4.7 kilometers
outside the city.
So Leonardo's
on the move.
Is the Captain with him?
Her combadge may have
malfunctioned.
Or she might have been
discovered.
Should I beam da Vinci
back to the ship?
If the Captain is with him
and attempting to recover
the processor,
she may need his assistance.
Keep a lock
on the mobile emitter,
and stand by.
KIM:
Aye, sir.
JANEWAY:
Where's the entrance?
DA VINCI:
I can't recall.
Why not?
These fortresses,
I've been to half
a dozen of them.
All are similar,
but each is different.
Catarina,
observe the construction,
like the veins and arteries
of a great animal.
Now, this is
the way to build,
using nature
as your guide.
No more lessons.
I need to get into
this building and I need
to get into it now.
That is not the way
an apprentice should address
her master.
Maestro, your prince is
going to come after us.
The only escape
is inside.
Escape?
We will be trapped inside.
No. There is a wondrous
invention inside this building.
It's called
a computer processor.
We can use to send
a beacon to...
to the Portuguese ship.
And they'll come
and rescue us.
Computer?
This invention,
how does it work?
Well, it's complicated...
but trust me when I say
it can send messages
over great distances.
All we have to do is find it
and we will be rescued.
But the question is,
how do we get inside?
Shadow and sunlight.
The prince, like
any other thief,
will fear theft
above all else.
So this stronghold will
have but one entryway,
on the side facing
away from the sun.
So the bright light
would be in the eyes of
anyone who might attack.
Esatto.
Hmm...
I'm no longer reading
the mobile emitter.
They've gone inside
the structure.
KIM:
Commander,
they are being pursued.
Over 30 armed guards
are converging on
the storage facility.
All available power
to the transporters.
Let's try to get them
out of there.
DA VINCI:
Even Theseus could not
negotiate this labyrinth.
JANEWAY:
Not without a compass.
( tricorder beeping )
Your compass
is speaking to you.
This way.
( distant clanging )
A trove of invention.
The prince has done
well for himself.
Phasers...
warp plasma injectors...
a site-to-site transporter.
Your computer?
Yes.
Computer, do you recognize
my voice?
COMPUTER:
Affirmative.
Well, that's a start.
Che bella!
There's a
mechanical woman inside.
In a way, yes.
Initiate a level-4
induction relay overload.
That procedure
is not recommended.
Command override,
Janeway-pi-one-one-zero.
Authorization confirmed.
Initiating overload.
That's it.
And now?
We wait for
the Portuguese.
TUVOK:
Commander, I'm detecting
a power surge
in the subspace
frequency range.
It could be the processor.
Lock on.
Increase power
to the confinement beam.
With any luck,
we might be able
to pull the Captain
out of there along with it.
( power surging )
Step close, Leonardo.
We're going
for a ride.
I don't understand.
Trust me.
The building is probably
surrounded by now.
There's only one way out.
Maestro, come here.
Catarina,
what just happened to me?
I was shot...yet I live.
Such things are not possible.
This is an invention
from another land.
It's called
a site-to-site transporter.
In the blink of an eye,
it can move us
out of this building,
and a few kilometers
away from here.
How?
Come on.
I must have
an explanation.
Leonardo,
you've always said
that it's
a poor apprentice
who can't surpass
her master.
There are things
in this world
that I understand,
and you don't.
( rapid beeping )
Madonna mia.
The processor is on board.
The Captain?
Still on the planet.
KIM:
Commander.
Thirteen vessels are
approaching Voyager
from the surface.
Tom, take us
into a higher orbit.
Bridge
to Torres.
I want that
processor
back on line.
We've still got
a Captain down there.
TORRES:
Acknowledged.
DA VINCI:
I cannot believe it.
I will not believe it.
My mind cannot accept
the evidence of my eyes.
Is this sorcery?
Are we in purgatory?
JANEWAY:
Neither.
You said yourself
this place was full
of marvels.
Marvels, yes,
but this is magic,
enchantment,
not science.
And I refuse to believe
in enchantment.
I'll explain later.
We've got to keep moving.
No!
I must understand.
Catarina...
to see objects disappear
into thin air...
to see lightning
pass through my body...
Are we spirits?
Catarina...am I dead?
Let me ask you something.
If you were something
other than a human being...
if you were a different
kind of animal...
( bird singing )
if you were a small bird,
a sparrow...
what would your world be like?
I should make my home
in a tree
in the branch of an elm.
I should hunt insects
for food,
straw for my nest,
and in the springtime,
I should sing for a companion.
Then you would know nothing
of the politics of Florence?
The cutting of marble,
or mathematics?
Of course not.
But why not?
My mind would be too small.
As a sparrow, your mind
would be too small
even with the best of teachers?
If Aristotle himself
were to perch on my branch,
and lecture till he fell off
from exhaustion...
still the limits of my mind
would prevent me
from understanding.
And as a man, can you accept
that there may be
certain realities
beyond the limits
of your comprehension?
If I could not accept that...
then I would be a fool.
MALE:
Spread out! You...
Come on.
Catarina, this way,
up the hill.
I know just
the escape.
Torres to Bridge.
We're in business.
We've got full navigation...
full propulsion,
and full transporters.
Good work B'Elanna.
Sensors show the
Captain and da Vinci
have left
the structure.
If we could dip
into a lower orbit,
I should be able to lock on
to the mobile emitter.
Set the confinement beam wide,
and prepare to transport
both of them back to the ship.
How close do we have to be?
At least 500 kilometers
from the surface.
Those ships will try
to block our descent.
Ready for some fancy flying?
You bet.
( da Vinci panting heavily )
Momento, Catarina.
( sighs )
Escape, signorina,
is very near.
I'm starting to wonder.
( whispers ):
Where are you, Chakotay?
Help me to the summit.
We're at 1,000 kilometers.
950...
900.
TUVOK:
The ships are
powering weapons.
Go to Red Alert.
Shields are holding.
Eight hundred fifty kilometers.
Evasive maneuvers.
DA VINCI:
When Petrarch climbed
Mount Verdoun,
and saw all Europe
below him,
he knew he was witnessing
the birth of a new age.
He was witnessing
the Renaissance,
the rebirth
of our world.
So, Catarina,
at this summit here,
you and I
will be reborn.
Reborn...with wings.
This could be a problem.
Hurry, there's
not much time.
Sir, they seem to be
on the edge of precipice,
but we're still too
high for transport.
You've made some
improvements.
I took your advice
after the last attempt,
and increased the
reach of the wings.
And the angle
of attack?
Yes, yes, that too.
Unfortunately, the River
Arno is quite absent.
This time, if we fail,
only the stones
will break our fall.
The wing is stationary,
that's good.
This looks like duranium alloy.
It should be light enough.
Catarina,
this time it will work.
( phaser shot )
Let's find out.
I'm reading weapons fire
on the surface
near the Captain's position.
We're running out
of time, sir.
Seven hundred kilometers.
Hold on, Kathryn,
just a few more seconds.
Together...up.
Andiamo.
( grunts )
Catarina, we're flying!
Like the birds!
( sighs )
I have a fix on the Captain.
They are...in mid-air,
on what appears to be
a crude gliding apparatus.
Five hundred kilometers!
KIM:
I'm locking on.
Broad confinement beam.
Energize.
Got them!
I beamed
the whole contraption into
Cargo Bay 1.
Get us out of here, Mr. Paris.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51408.3.
We're back on course
to the Alpha Quadrant.
With the ship's computer,
and the Doctor's emitter
returned to proper places,
I've set aside some time
to check on the Maestro.
( door closes )
Leonardo, where
are you going?
France.
These Florentines
do not deserve my genius.
I have written
to the king of France,
telling him of my adventures
in the New World,
and invited him to soar with me
off the towers of his castle.
Are you sure
that's a good idea?
Why not?
We ourselves have tested
the design.
But the materials...
you'll never find
those metals in France.
No?
Then others will suffice.
Machines that fly
through the air!
Lightning flung
from one's hands!
Mechanical women
who live in boxes!
These things I have seen!
And these things
I must recreate.
And who knows?
Possibly improve upon.
Leonardo, I think
that little flight of ours
went to your head.
And my heart.
My oldest memory, Catarina,
is of a great bird
perched on my bed,
its feathers open towards me
as if summoning me.
Now, you yourself,
have accused me of giving up,
of, uh, failing to
complete my project.
I was trying
to encourage--
No, no.
You were right.
All my life
I have wanted to fly.
Perhaps my failure to do so
has caused my heart
to remain in flight.
Leaping from one thing
to another.
Never satisfied.
Never complete.
And now, that you've
actually flown?
Now, who knows what
I cannot accomplish.
I'd like to find out.
Give my regards
to the king of France.
Catarina,
will you walk with me
to my carriage?
It would be my pleasure.