Thank you.
Oh, you look like a man
who could use more coffee.
Keep it coming.
I'm working on
my monthly ops report.
So much has happened in
the last few weeks on this ship,
I'm going to be up
all night.
This firenut blend
should keep your eyes open.
Potent stuff. Thanks.
( chuckles )
Neelix.
Yes.
I know you have your hands
full this evening,
but I could use your help.
At your service,
Commander.
We're approaching
a class-1 nebula.
Sensors are picking up traces
of protomatter inside.
I understand you've
dealt with it before.
Absolutely, when I was
making my living as a trader.
Protomatter's one of the most
sought-after commodities.
It's the best energy source
in the Quadrant.
Well, we could use
your expertise
in collecting a sample.
We're leaving at 1400.
See you in the shuttle bay?
I'll be there, sir.
These nutritional supplements
are unacceptable.
What's wrong?
They are pungent.
That's the whole idea.
I've been adding
Talaxian spices
to broaden your palate.
My palate is
sufficiently broad.
Why settle for
"sufficient"?
The doctor tells me
you have a full complement
of taste buds.
You've hardly begun
to use them.
Come by the Mess Hall
Thursday night.
It's the first day of Prixin.
We'll have an impressive array
of exotic cuisine.
Prixin?
The Talaxian celebration
of family.
We observe it every year
on Voyager.
Now that you're
part of the family...
What should I do
to prepare?
Nothing.
It's not a mission, Seven.
It's a party.
( com link chirps )
SAMANTHA:
Ensign Wildman to Neelix.
Uh, Neelix here.
SAMANTHA: I hate to bother you,
but Naomi's having trouble
getting to sleep again.
Would you mind?
No bother at all.
I'm on my way.
If you'll excuse me,
duty calls.
"Naomi"... I don't recall
that designation
on the crew manifest.
That's because she's not
a member of the crew.
Naomi was the first child
born on Voyager.
I'm her godfather,
and the only one that can
get her to sleep lately.
Bon appetit.
( sighing )
No monsters here.
Good.
Check the replicator.
( grunts )
Ah. Nothing.
Naomi, maybe Neelix
should check your room
so you can go to bed.
Okay.
In there.
Nobody here.
There.
Ah, there's not
a monster in sight.
Can you stay longer?
I'm afraid to go to sleep.
Honey, Neelix has
to go to work.
Oh, it's all right.
You know what I think about
when I'm afraid to go to sleep?
NAOMI:
No. What?
The Great Forest.
What's that?
It's a place my people believe
we're all going to go to
someday.
It's a beautiful, beautiful
forest filled with sunlight,
and all the people who ever
loved me are gathered there
to watch over me as I sleep,
to protect me.
NAOMI:
Really?
Mm-hmm, and when I think about
that forest and those people,
I'm not afraid to sleep anymore.
Do you think those people
watch over me too?
I know they do.
Now, I'm going to be away
for the next couple of days,
so if you're afraid to sleep,
I want you to think
of that Great Forest.
All right.
Pleasant dreams.
NAOMI:
Night, Neelix.
Thank you.
Cylinder...
( clanking )
Oh!
Sorry.
I didn't realize you were home.
I was regenerating.
I see.
Do you require assistance?
No, no, no,
I have a small
containment cylinder
stored here.
I'll just be a minute.
Cylinder...
Little cylinder, where are you?
Cylinder, you were here
a month ago.
Now, I know you
didn't just roll
out of the airlock
all by yourself.
Now, where are you?
Oh...
( laughing ):
I'm sorry.
I'm talking to myself. It's
my way of remembering things.
You are a peculiar creature,
Neelix.
Thanks.
I think.
Ah! Here it is.
Oh, this will be perfect
for containing
a small amount of protomatter.
Last time I used
this little wonder,
I nearly lost it to the Kazon.
The Kazon...species 329.
You're familiar with them.
The Borg encountered
a Kazon colony
in the Gand Sector.
Grid 6920.
Were they assimilated?
Their biological and
technological distinctiveness
was unremarkable.
They were unworthy
of assimilation.
I didn't realize the Borg
were so discriminating.
Why assimilate a species
that would detract
from perfection?
Good point.
Well, um, if you'll excuse me,
I'm needed in the shuttle bay.
Pleasant...
regenerating.
( dramatic theme playing )
One day a week,
that's all I ask.
How hard can it be?
Harder than you think.
Neelix, it's pizza!
Bread, tomatoes, cheese.
The cheese alone
would take days.
Separating curds and whey
from synthesized milk--
It's a delicate process.
So replicate the cheese!
Since it means so much to you,
I'll see what I can do.
Thanks.
( console beeping )
There's a concentration
of protomatter directly ahead.
Neelix?
Set the transporter
for 10,000 AMUs.
Not a particle more.
The containment field
is standing by.
PARIS:
We're in range.
Energizing.
What happened?
The transporter beam
ignited the protomatter.
Shields are weakening.
Disengage transport.
PARIS:
Shields are down!
I've got the sample, Commander,
and it's stable.
Let's get out of--
( groaning )
We're clear of the protomatter.
How's Neelix?
( tricorder sounding
steady tone )
( exhales )
He's dead.
( triumphant theme playing )
No heartbeat.
No synaptic response.
Extensive cell damage
to his brain.
Try a cortical stimulator.
( rumble )
It won't work.
His neural pathways were
disrupted by the protomatter.
Set the stimulator
for an autonomic bypass.
At least, we can get
his vitals going.
It's too late for that.
The damage was too severe.
(rumble )
We're running into
more protomatter.
I need your help.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51449.2.
After receiving a distress call
from Commander Chakotay,
we've sent a beacon
into the nebula
and we're in the process of
tracking down the away team.
Captain, I'm detecting
a shuttle.
JANEWAY:
Hail them.
No response.
TUVOK:
The shuttle's primary
systems are off-line.
Life signs, only two.
Are they within
transporter range?
Affirmative.
Beam them
directly to Sickbay.
Harry, put a tractor
on the shuttlecraft.
Tuvok, you've got
the Bridge.
I ran a complete
postmortem analysis.
There was nothing
you could have done.
I knew we were too close
to the protomatter.
I should have
said something.
Nobody could have
predicted this, Tom.
How shall I...
proceed?
The Talaxians mourn
their dead for a full week
in a specific
burial ceremony.
And that's just what
we're going to do.
I'll inform the crew.
I'll check Neelix's
personal database,
see what I can find out
about the ceremony.
We'll have it
in the Mess Hall.
Somehow that feels
appropriate.
Neelix is dead.
I'm afraid so.
His neural pathways--
are they intact?
DOCTOR:
Yes,
but there's
no metabolic activity.
How long has he been dead?
Seven, I understand--
How long?
PARIS:
It's been 18 hours.
Then it's not too late
to reactivate him.
What are you saying--
that you can bring
Neelix back to life?
That's precisely
what I'm saying.
The Borg have
assimilated species
with far greater medical
knowledge than your own.
We are capable of
reactivating drones
as much as 73 hours after
what you would call "death."
Neelix wasn't a Borg drone.
We will adapt.
What does this procedure
involve?
Nanoprobes are used
to reverse
cellular necrosis,
while the cerebral cortex
is stimulated
with a neuroelectric
iso-pulse.
But there's nothing
left to stimulate.
His brain functions
are gone.
By your narrow definition
perhaps, but not by mine.
You will extract
70 micrograms of nanoprobes
from my bloodstream.
I will modify them
to match
his Talaxian physiology.
His function in this crew
is diverse.
If you wish to salvage him,
we must proceed immediately.
I say we let her try.
Hold on a minute, Tom,
please.
No one's ever been resuscitated
after being dead for 18 hours.
If this procedure does work,
what are the chances that Neelix
would come out of it unaffected?
She's right.
The damage to his cerebral
cortex was severe.
The nanoprobes will compensate
for any cellular degradation.
Captain, a decision
has to be made, quickly.
Doctor, give Seven
whatever assistance she needs.
Proceed.
Captain...
JANEWAY: Do it.
If there's a chance
we can revive Neelix,
we've got to take it.
Keep me informed.
( dramatic theme playing )
( console beeping )
The nanoprobes are ready.
We should begin.
Hold on, I want to check
his blood viscosity.
The cadaver has been
sufficiently prepared.
And they say I have
a lousy bedside manner.
Set neuroelectric iso-pulses
for one-second intervals.
( doctor sighing )
( beeping )
Ready.
Now.
( bio-bed beeping )
Neural activity
at nine percent...
10 percent...
12 percent.
This is incredible!
His intracerebral
blood pressure,
his synaptic responses--
they're all returning
to normal.
The alveoli in his lung
are regenerating.
They should be functional...
( Neelix gasping deeply )
...now.
Neural activity at
52 percent and rising.
( grunting softly )
His neurotransmitter
levels
are rising too fast.
We must stabilize
his motor neurons.
I'm going to try reducing
his acetylcholine levels.
It might be enough to--
NEELIX: Doctor...
Neelix.
What...happened?
What happened?
Why am...
Why am I here?
( dramatic theme playing )
Dead.
For 18 hours,
49 minutes,
13 seconds.
Congratulations,
Mr. Neelix.
You've just set
a new world record.
That's impossible.
You mean,
I lost consciousness.
I-I was--
I was in a coma.
No. You were dead.
I'm stunned.
I'm amazed.
I-I'm grateful.
Thank you, doctor.
Actually, you can
thank Seven of Nine.
The procedure
was her idea.
Yours?
The Borg assimilated
the technique from species 149.
I simply modified it.
But you are welcome.
Am I good as new?
That remains to be seen.
There's no way to tell
if your body
will successfully
take over the functions
the nanoprobes
are serving.
Nanoprobes?
It was necessary
to repair
the necrotized tissue.
Until I'm certain
the damaged tissue
can function independently,
you'll have to be injected
with nanoprobes
on a daily basis.
Well, as long as I don't start,
uh, assimilating the crew
or sprouting Borg implants...
I'm sure
I can live with it.
I'm releasing you
to your quarters.
Your body's
been through quite a shock,
so try to get
some rest.
Report to Sickbay
tomorrow morning
at 0800 hours for
your next injection.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
The shuttle mission,
was it a success?
Did we get
the protomatter?
I'm afraid not.
The sample you collected
destabilized
before it got back
to Voyager.
Ugh. The containment field needs
to be reinforced next time.
If there is a next time.
I've asked Chakotay
to find out exactly
what caused the accident,
and unless we can take
additional precautions,
I'm not sending another team
into that nebula.
I could help with
that investigation.
No. You are taking
some time off,
and that's an order.
No, Captain, please,
I don't need
any special treatment.
Neelix, you've just
returned from the dead.
Go easy on yourself.
I suppose you're right.
But you can't ask me to cancel
the first night of Prixin.
The celebration
is in three days.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I've been aging fruit compote
in moolt nectar for weeks now.
I-I can't just let it
go to waste.
Only if you feel up to it.
Oh...
But could you not ferment those
compotes so long this time?
Because last year,
I got a little lightheaded.
I'll make
the necessary adjustments.
It's good
to have you back.
It's good to be back,
Captain.
( dramatic theme playing )
Alixia?
Why weren't you there?
Human attitudes toward death
are perplexing.
How so?
Too much importance
is placed on it.
There seem to be countless
rituals and cultural beliefs
designed to alleviate their fear
of a simple, biological truth.
All organisms
eventually perish.
I take it the Borg have no fear
of that biological truth.
None. When a drone is damaged
beyond repair, it is discarded,
but its memories continue
to exist
in the
collective consciousness.
To use a human term,
the Borg are "immortal."
You are no longer
part of the collective.
You are mortal now,
like the rest of us.
Does that disturb you?
My connection to the Borg
has been severed,
but the collective still
possesses my recollections,
my experiences.
In a sense,
I will always exist.
Fascinating.
That must be a great relief.
Yes.
It is.
I've sealed the fractures
in the shuttle nacelle.
The rest of the repairs
should be completed by morning.
Good.
How are you coming?
I found a small
phase variance
in the
transporter logs.
I think it was
responsible
for igniting
the protomatter.
I've remodulated the transporter
beam to compensate.
( beeps )
Good work.
I'll be in Holodeck 2.
I've created a simulation
of the shuttle accident
to see if there's anything
we've overlooked.
( dramatic theme playing )
Commander. Commander,
I thought you might need
some assistance on
the holodeck.
If you're feeling up to it.
Well, I'm up to anything
at this point.
I've been resting
for two days straight,
and resting makes me
feel, well, restless.
( chuckles )
I've programmed
the simulation
to start when we found
the protomatter.
Why don't you monitor
the containment field readings?
( console beeping)
Gladly.
Computer, display
shuttle crew,
excluding myself,
and begin program.
There's a concentration
of protomatter directly ahead.
Set the transporter
for 10,000 AMUs.
Not a particle more.
The containment field
is standing by.
We're in range.
( rumble )
The transporter beam
ignited the protomatter.
Computer,
freeze program.
It looks like there
was a problem
with the pattern buffer.
It might have created
a feedback loop
along the
transporter beam.
Sounds right.
Let's keep
an eye on it.
See what happened
at the moment of impact.
Computer,
resume program.
( rumble )
Shields are weakening.
Shields are down!
I've got the sample, Commander,
and it's stable.
Let's get out of--
( groaning )
Computer,
freeze program.
( dramatic theme playing )
Nothing.
What?
I died,
and there was nothing.
There was no one there.
No forest.
Forest?
The Great Forest.
The afterlife.
I was taught
that when I died,
my ancestors would be there
waiting for me
by the Guiding Tree.
My sisters, my mother
and father, my cousins...
everyone who was killed
in the war.
( shudders )
I took great comfort
in knowing that we'd all
be together again one day,
but it's not true.
Maybe we pulled you back
before any of that
could happen.
No.
I was dead for 18 hours.
I should have...
...experienced something.
I should remember something!
It's just a story.
A myth.
There is no Guiding Tree.
No gathering
of the ancestors.
You can't be certain
of that.
Don't throw away
a lifetime of faith
because of one
anomalous incident.
Death is still the greatest
mystery there is.
I was there.
I experienced it.
There was nothing.
Computer, delete characters.
( computer beeps )
That's what's going to happen
to all of us.
Like a hologram, we just...
disappear into nothing.
( chatting indistinctly )
( mellow theme playing )
TUVOK:
Attention.
If I may have
everyone's attention.
( people continue chatting
indistinctly )
You might wanna try the old
"glass and spoon" approach.
"Glass and spoon"?
Excuse me.
( chatting ceases )
Thank you.
Welcome to the first night
of Prixin,
the Talaxian observance
of familial allegiance.
This year,
Mr. Neelix has requested
that I
commence the celebration
with the traditional
salutation.
"We do not stand alone.
"We are in the arms of family.
"Father, mother,
"sister, brother,
"father's father,
"father's mother,
"father's brother,
"mother's brother...
fath..."
Suffice to say,
the list is extensive.
( light chuckling )
"We gather on this day
to extol the warmth and joy
"of those unshakable bonds.
"Without them, we could not
call ourselves complete.
"On this day,
we are thankful to be together.
We do not stand alone."
JANEWAY:
Indeed, we do not.
MAN: Here, here.
( applause )
A few days ago, we almost lost
a member of our family.
I don't know how
the rest of you feel,
but it scared
the hell out of me.
Neelix,
you still don't know
how to make a pizza...
( laughter )
...but I'm glad you're here.
So am I.
Here's to you, Neelix.
( crowd toasting Neelix )
( dramatic theme playing )
( applause )
MAN:
Speech.
Well...
Thank you, everyone.
( gasps )
...enjoy.
( crowd chuckles )
Computer, music.
( computer beeping )
( soft music plays )
( people chatting indistinctly )
You all right?
Fine, Commander, fine.
I apologize for the other day
on the holodeck.
I guess this whole "back
from the dead" thing
is hard to get used to.
I'm fine now.
If you ever wanna talk,
you know where to find me.
Having fun?
No.
That's probably
because you've been
standing here by yourself.
I don't understand
the rules and procedures
for this type of...
social occasion.
The rules are simple.
Choose a group
of people.
Listen to
their conversation.
Then when you feel
like you have something
to contribute, chime in.
"Chime in"?
You say something.
Join the discussion.
( sighs ):
I will try, Captain.
The early stages of Ktarian
development are astounding.
Naomi has grown five centimeters
since her last physical
and that was only
three weeks ago.
It seems like every time
I turn around,
I'm recycling her clothes
back into the replicator.
Children assimilated
by the Borg
are placed
in maturation chambers
for 17 cycles.
Interesting.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I need to go talk to Neelix.
In these
maturation chambers,
the development of
conversational skills
is, I suppose,
a low priority?
SAMANTHA: Neelix.
Oh!
( tray clangs )
SAMANTHA: I'm sorry.
No, no, no,
it's all right.
We haven't seen you
in a few days.
I've been
a little preoccupied.
I understand.
Naomi's been asking
about you.
Really?
She misses you,
and, frankly, so do I.
She's had trouble sleeping
every night this week.
"Only Neelix
can tuck me in."
"I want Neelix."
Heh, it sounds familiar.
Maybe you could stop by
later just to say hello.
Why don't--
Why don't I go now?
It's close to
Naomi's bedtime.
Are you sure?
Prixin's
your favorite holiday.
Yes, but duty calls.
Attention,
all monsters.
Get out of this room!
My bed!
Oh, there's
no monsters here.
Aah! It's a monster!
Hee-hee!
Scared you!
Heh, heh.
You certainly did.
Pleasant dreams,
sweeting.
Can you stay longer?
I want to hear about
the Great Forest again.
The Great Forest?
NAOMI: The special place.
The place you think about
when you can't sleep.
Are you sure you want
to hear about that?
It's just a silly old story.
Please.
( dramatic theme playing )
Well...
it's a beautiful place,
filled with sunlight...
And all the people
who ever loved me.
Yes. They've all
gathered there...
to watch over you,
to protect you
while you sleep.
I had a dream about
the Great Forest last night.
You did?
There was trees,
and grass,
and animals.
And I saw you and Mommy,
and we were all happy.
Sounds like a nice dream.
NAOMI:
It was beautiful.
( door opens )
The doctor asked me
to run a hematological scan.
Why?
To regulate the dosage
of nanoprobes
for your next injection.
( beeping )
Go ahead.
How much longer will I
be needing these injections?
Until your damaged cells
can function on their own.
I don't really like
the idea of Borg technology
swimming around inside me.
That is irrelevant.
You need the nanoprobes
to live.
"Live"?
Oh, is that what I am doing
right now, living?
I'm beginning to wonder.
By most definitions,
you are alive.
Well, part of me
isn't alive.
Which part
are you referring to?
I don't know,
but something is missing.
I don't feel
like Neelix anymore.
Maybe Neelix is gone.
Maybe he died,
and I'm all that's left.
Stop moving, and allow me
to complete the scan.
I-I didn't ask
to be brought back!
You were dead at the time.
Well, what right did you have
to violate me?
You Borg think
you can fix anything,
but you didn't fix me!
There was no alternative.
Just get out.
Just leave me alone!
I said get out!
I would be negligent in
my duties if I did that.
I don't care about
your duties!
I don't care--
( gasping )
( dramatic theme playing )
( groaning )
( instruments beeping )
( gasps )
What's...
What's happening to me?
( choking )
Your cells are reverting
to a necrotic state.
We must get you to Sickbay.
His tissue began
rejecting the nanoprobes,
causing spontaneous necrosis
throughout his body.
We modified the nanoprobes
to compensate
and it appears to be working.
Neelix is stable...
for now.
How do we know
this won't happen again?
We don't. I've designed
a monitor for Neelix to wear
that will alert us
at the first sign of necrosis,
and we'll continue
with the daily injections.
Beyond that,
I'm afraid it's a...
matter of maintenance.
He may have to live with
this condition
for the rest of his life.
He wants to speak
with you, Commander.
Commander...you said
if I ever needed anything.
You once told me
your people had technology
that can induce
a deep meditation,
an altered state of
consciousness.
The akoonah.
That this device allows you
to look inside yourself,
ask questions that you might
otherwise be afraid to ask.
That's right.
That's what I need.
I need to look inside
myself...
figure out
what's happening to me.
I need answers.
Will you help me, Commander?
All right...
but I want you to understand
the vision quest isn't
a quick fix.
It'll take time
to interpret the images,
and there's no guarantee
you'll find
what you're looking for.
I understand.
What should I do to prepare?
You'll need a medicine bundle.
Items that define you,
things that will ground you,
allow you to take the journey
into yourself.
I'll get ready.
This belonged to
my sister, Alixia.
She made it during
our expedition
to
the Dunes of Talmouth.
A flower from Kes' garden.
And last, but not least,
the Guiding Tree.
It stands at the center of
Talaxian afterlife,
deep inside
the Great Forest.
It's there to help us
find our way
when we first arrive.
At least, that's what
I used to believe.
Not a very impressive
medicine bundle, is it?
It'll do fine.
Now, place your hand
on the akoonah.
( beeping )
Am I doing this right?
Try to relax.
Clear your mind of everything
but the objects before you.
Focus on them.
Nothing else exists.
( dramatic theme playing )
Ah-koo-chee-moya.
We are far
from the sacred places
of our grandfathers.
We are far
from the bones of our people.
We come here
seeking guidance.
It's time, Neelix.
Try to leave this room,
this ship...
and go to a place
where you were
the most peaceful and content
you have ever been.
That's where your journey
will begin.
( people chatting indistinctly )
Neelix...good
to have you back.
It's-it's good to be
back, Lieutenant.
Alixia?
Alixia, it's me, Neelix!
Over here.
Captain!
My sister--
She was just standing here
talking to you.
The dead girl.
Oh, yes. Very charming.
I can see
the family resemblance.
Alixia!
You will be
assimilated.
No time for that now.
Maybe later.
Potent stuff.
It's... It's beautiful.
Yes. It's just like you
always imagined it would be.
The trees, the sunlight,
and all the people
who ever loved you.
When I died, I looked for you,
but you weren't there.
Why weren't you there?
Because it's all a lie.
What do you mean?
You've wasted your entire life
believing lies.
The Great Forest.
The afterlife.
It's all created
out of your fear of death.
None of it's real.
If that's true,
what's the point of living?
There isn't any.
That's what
you're finally
starting to realize.
( in Naomi's voice ):
I'm afraid to go to sleep.
Tell me about the Great Forest,
Neelix.
Tell me about the trees
and the grass
and all the people
who loved you.
Why are you saying
these things?
( Naomi's voice ):
Scared you!
( gasping )
( thunder rumbles )
( eerie animal calls )
You died on that
shuttlecraft, Neelix.
They never should have
brought you back.
It was a mistake,
and you know it.
Now accept it.
You know what you have to do.
No.
It's all a lie.
They lied to you.
You know what you have to do.
We gather on this day
to tell Neelix what he must do.
You stand alone.
Life is irrelevant.
Let go.
It's pointless.
It's a lie.
You know what you have to do.
( screaming ):
No!
( shudders )
SEVEN:
Neelix.
Oh, there you are.
I didn't see you.
Are you looking
for me?
Yes, as a matter
of fact, I am.
I hope I'm not
disturbing you.
You are not.
I...
I want to apologize for
my outburst the other day
in the Mess Hall.
No apology is necessary.
No. No, please,
my behavior was uncalled for.
I didn't mean
the things I said.
I wasn't myself.
But I feel much better now.
Commander Chakotay
has helped me to...
understand a few things.
I want you to know
that I don't blame you
for bringing me back.
To life, I mean.
In fact, what you did
was very thoughtful.
I would have done the same
for any member of this crew.
Yes. I'm sure
you would have.
Is there
something else?
No.
Yes.
Seven, I think you've made
a wonderful addition
to this crew.
I know it's been
difficult for you
making the transition
from Borg back to human.
Or half human.
Or whatever it is
you've become.
Actually, you're
just plain Seven to me.
Your point, Mr. Neelix.
I guess I just want to say...
you're surrounded
by people
who care about you.
And whether you
know it or not,
Voyager is going to be
a very good home to you.
It certainly was to me.
Was?
Do you intend to leave?
Leave?
No. I'll be around.
Well...
...good-bye.
Good-bye.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
What happened to you
this morning?
I'm sorry I had to cancel
our little chat,
but I was needed
in the Mess Hall.
I've been so busy
the last few days,
I let things slip
around here.
You're not holding up
your end of the bargain.
What do you mean?
When you asked me to guide you
on a vision quest, I agreed,
but I also told you it was part
of an ongoing process.
We're supposed to be
discussing your progress.
What's left to say?
I've told you--
I saw my sister,
the Great Forest.
I feel a sense of peace
I've never felt
in my entire life.
It worked.
You've only lived
with the visions
for a couple of days.
That's not enough time
to draw any conclusions.
You've got to reflect
on the images, examine them.
Allow them to stay alive
in your mind.
A vision quest isn't just
a dream you dismiss
after your first
cup of coffee.
I understand.
Good.
I get off duty
at 1400 hours.
Meet me in my quarters
and we'll begin.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
( door opens, closes )
( somber theme playing )
Computer, lights off.
( computer beeps )
And finally, Mr. Tuvok...
I'm grateful for the opportunity
I had to win your respect.
Your strength and your wisdom
were an inspiration to me,
and I can only hope
that your memory of me
will serve to inspire you
in some way.
It was an honor to spend my last
years on Voyager with this crew.
I want to thank all of you
for your kindness and
companionship.
Good-bye.
( computer beeps )
Computer, end log
and code for delivery
to Captain Janeway
in one hour.
( computer beeps )
( beeping )
( console beeping )
Captain, someone's trying
to initiate
an unauthorized
transport.
It's Neelix.
Where's he going?
Looks like he's trying
to beam into the nebula.
Stop him.
Janeway to Neelix.
Neelix, respond.
Neelix, I order you
to disengage transport.
He's found a way
to block the abort sequence.
Transport's in progress.
Override it! Get him back!
( suspenseful theme playing )
( com link beeps )
KIM: Bridge to Chakotay.
We've blocked
his transporter signal.
You can slow me down,
but you can't stop me.
What are you trying to do?
I'm going back where I belong.
You belong here, Neelix.
Not anymore.
I died in that nebula!
You should've left me!
Neelix...
No closer!
I've created
a site-to-site transport.
No one can override
the signal.
You told me
you were at peace.
I will be...
as soon as I tap this control.
What really happened
in your vision quest?
What did you see?
My sister, the crew, myself.
They all told me
the same thing--
There's no point in living.
And I agree with them.
I'm sure
those were powerful images,
but there are many ways
to interpret them.
You may be coming face-to-face
with your own fear of death.
Or the manifestation
of your emotional crisis.
Your deepest beliefs
have been thrown into doubt.
It's only natural the vision
quest would reflect that.
Eleven years ago,
I saw my world in ruins...
...my family murdered.
All that's kept me going
is knowing that one day
we'd be together again.
That I'd see them again.
But it's not true.
And I can't...live
without that hope.
I understand how this
can change
the way you look at things,
but it can also
lead to an even stronger faith.
You don't know.
You're not there yet.
( com link beeps )
SAMANTHA:
Ensign Wildman to Neelix.
Answer her!
Neelix, please respond.
No.
You're being called
back to your life again, Neelix.
Don't turn
your back on it.
We're your family now.
It's not enough.
It is for us.
"His function on this crew
is diverse."
That's what Seven of Nine
said about you.
Even our Borg understands
how important
you are on this ship.
It's not just the duties
you perform.
It's the way you make people
feel when you're around.
That Neelix is gone.
I don't think he is.
Why didn't you
answer me?
I had to have the computer
track you down.
Naomi thought she saw
a monster in the replicator.
Neelix, what's going on?
I'm trying to decide
some things.
That little girl
needs you, Neelix.
Monsters in the replicator?
Who else on this ship
can handle that?
( gulps )
( dramatic theme playing )
Duty calls.
Good night, sir.
He says good night.
Good night, Naomi.
Good night.
What's the matter?
Mommy says
you were sick.
I was, but I'm okay now.
Did a monster
get you?
Yes, I suppose so.
But I chased him away.
Pleasant dreams.
( tranquil theme playing )
( triumphant theme playing )