( sighing )
Ensign Kim.
I require your assistance
in Jefferies Tube 37-Alpha.
Well, can it wait?
I just got off duty.
It is urgent.
Hmm.
Bridge to Commander Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
You're needed
on the Bridge, sir.
On my way.
Computer, lights on.
Neelix?
Is anybody here?
CHAKOTAY:
Voyager to Lieutenant Paris.
Paris here.
How's it going out there, Tom?
One more orbit and I should have
all the data we need.
Good work.
See you when you get back.
Chakotay out.
Crewman. Ensign.
Sir.
Hello, sir.
( sighs )
It looks to me
like you aligned
the power couplings perfectly.
I did.
If you're so sure,
then why'd you need
me to look at them?
I did not.
( laughs )
Then what's
this all about?
I've learned from observing
Lieutenants Torres and Paris
that humans sometimes
require a pretext
for being intimate
with one another.
Intimate?
( grunts )
Resistance is futile.
( moaning )
( grunts )
Paris to Voyager.
CHAKOTAY:
Voyager here.
My primary warp manifold
just ruptured.
I've lost helm control.
Auxiliary power is off-line.
Thrusters won't respond.
Say again, Tom.
Your signal's breaking up.
My orbit's decaying.
I don't think I can hold it.
Repeat that, Tom.
I need an emergency beam-out!
Voyager to Lieutenant Paris.
Come in!
Neelix?
What can I do
for you, Captain?
Where is everybody?
Didn't you see them
when you came in?
No.
Take a look.
Computer,
activate lights.
( Janeway gasps )
Lieutenant Commander Tuvok
reporting for duty.
( all laughing )
Is something wrong?
I think you forgot something,
Tuvok.
( laughing continues )
It appears that, in my haste
to report to the Bridge,
I neglected
to put on my uniform.
( laughing )
JANEWAY:
What happened to them?
NEELIX:
They died.
Why?
You didn't get
them home in time.
( gasps )
( screaming )
( moans )
( panting )
( yawning )
( door chimes )
Hello.
Good morning.
Sleep well?
Not really.
What are you doing here?
I just thought
I'd stop by and ask you
why you didn't meet me
for breakfast.
Breakfast...
What time is it?
7:40.
And we were supposed
to meet at 0700.
I was there--
right after I got
off the night shift.
I waited... and I waited
and I called you on the com.
I... uh... I-I
didn't hear you.
I was having this
wild nightmare.
I was out like a light.
I'm sorry. I'll get
dressed right now.
You don't have time. You're due
on the Bridge at 0800,
and I've got
to get some sleep.
Oh, I hate this!
We never see each other.
I'm off Friday night.
Great.
Let's go skiing.
How about Saint Moritz?
We went skiing
last time.
And you loved it.
You're getting
really good, you know.
I just thought maybe
we could run a program
where the wind chill factor
wasn't 30 below zero...
like... Fiji
or Samoa.
Oh. There's nothing
to do there.
And you can be warm while
you're not doing it.
How about a compromise?
Um...
spring skiing in Chile?
Much warmer.
A compromise...
How about Tahiti?
Hmm. Tahiti.
As long as I can
go waterskiing, fine.
You're on.
Now, go get dressed,
so you'll at least have time
to stop for some coffee.
I'll see you Friday night.
( sighs )
Morning, Tom.
Mm.
What will it be?
Scrambled, sunny-side up,
over easy?
Just a cup of coffee.
Are you sure?
Breakfast is the most important
meal of the day, you know.
Neelix!
Right.
Uh...
Neelix...
did you have a rough
night or something?
Why do you ask?
Because you just poured me
a steaming cup of cooking oil.
Actually, I did have
a little trouble sleeping
last night.
Nightmares.
Oh.
Me, too.
Must have been
those three full moons
we passed yesterday.
Well, a few sips of my coffee
should clear the fuzz
out of your brain.
Maybe you should pour yourself
a cup while you're at it.
Seem to be
a little shorthanded today.
Tom and Harry
are both late.
I was going to give them
another five minutes,
but I'll call them now,
if you'd like.
That's all right.
I'm a little late myself,
aren't I?
I wasn't going to mention it.
Burning the midnight oil?
Actually, I went to bed early
for a change,
but I had a nightmare and
I could not get back to sleep.
I had a bad dream
last night, too.
You tell me yours and
I'll tell you mine.
Sorry I'm late,
Captain.
Well?
I was in the forest
with my father.
We were hunting deer,
which was odd,
because that was something
I always refused to do.
We cornered the animal.
I looked to my father to see
if he was going to kill it,
but he wasn't my father anymore.
He was a vicious-looking alien.
There was an alien
in my dream, too.
And it wasn't from any race
I've seen before. He had...
sharp ridges on his forehead
and on the front of his neck.
That's what mine looked like.
I don't mean
to be eavesdropping, but...
I had a nightmare
last night, too,
and I'm pretty sure
I saw the same guy.
Tuvok?
By any chance
did you have a bad dream
last night?
I did have a somewhat
unsettling dream, yes.
It involved an alien
with ridges
on his face and neck.
I'd say this sounds like
more than a coincidence.
Let's get the rest
of the senior staff together
and come up with some answers.
Which reminds me, where's Harry?
Bridge to Ensign Kim.
Computer, locate Ensign Kim.
Ensign Kim is in his quarters.
Tuvok.
Deck 6.
I've got a hunch
Harry's dreaming about
our new alien friend.
That would be consistent
with the experiences
the rest of us have had.
Tell me more
about your dream.
Where exactly did
you see the alien?
As a matter of fact, it was
here in the turbolift.
What happened?
The alien simply stared at me
as if scrutinizing
my appearance.
That's what happened
in my dream.
What did you do?
I returned to my quarters.
Did the alien follow you?
He did.
And then?
He watched me.
Doing what?
Getting dressed.
Getting dressed?
Yes.
I don't suppose I should ask
why you were undressed.
I would prefer
that you didn't.
( door buzzes )
Harry?
Computer,
open door 105-2.
Security clearance:
Tuvok-zeta-nine.
Harry?
Harry, wake up.
Are they comatose?
Not exactly.
They all appear to be
in a hyper-REM state.
I've tried every conventional
method of waking them--
from drugs to direct
cortical stimulation--
but nothing works.
Do you have any idea
what's causing this?
Scans haven't detected
any viral or bacterial agents.
No cranial trauma,
no neural disorders.
They're simply... asleep.
I'd say it's a pretty good bet
this is somehow related
to the alien
from our dreams.
Any progress
in identifying him?
Not yet, but I've got
everyone working on it.
In the meantime,
what's your recommendation?
Large doses of animazine.
I thought you said
drugs weren't working.
Not for them.
For everybody else.
Until I can determine
what's happening
I'd suggest the rest of you
avoid going to sleep.
I'd say his ridges were
a little more pronounced.
Computer, increase
facial ridge height
by four centimeters.
PARIS:
That's closer.
I think his eyes
were wider apart.
Computer, increase the space
between the eyes
by three centimeters.
Increase skin color
and texture.
That's him.
Has anybody seen
this species before?
While you
were awake, I mean.
Seven?
He doesn't resemble any species
assimilated by the Borg.
PARIS:
So is he just a figment
of our imagination?
TORRES:
If he is, we've all been
imagining the exact same thing.
One possible explanation
is that he's attempting
to make telepathic contact.
He's doing more
than making contact.
We've got six crew members
who can't wake up.
For all we know,
it's some sort of attack.
From where?
Astrometric scans
haven't revealed any ships
in this vicinity
or planets capable of
sustaining humanoid life.
So where do we look?
In our dreams.
That's the only place
any of us have seen him, right?
So, if we want
to communicate with him--
find out what he wants--
we'll have to do it
on his terms.
How do you propose
we do that?
Lucid dreaming.
What's that?
It's a technique
which allows you to
take control of your dream.
That happened to me once.
I dreamt I was falling
and suddenly I realized
that I was dreaming
and I could fly, land...
do whatever I wanted.
I was in complete
control of the dream.
What happened
to you by accident
is something some people
can do by design.
I've been able
to have a lucid dream
by using the same technology
I use for a vision quest.
I may be able to use it
to communicate
with this alien.
Maybe so.
But how do we know you'd
be able to wake up again?
It's kind of like
self-hypnosis.
Before I go to sleep,
I choose a visual cue--
something to let me
know I'm dreaming--
Earth's moon, say.
Once I see it,
I can wake myself
by tapping the back
of my hand three times.
TUVOK:
Perhaps you are capable
of doing this under
normal circumstances,
but these were hardly
conventional dreams
we experienced.
I don't see
any other way
of finding out what our
friend here is after,
or how we can wake up
Harry and the others.
Besides, we can't
stay awake forever.
You'll do this in Sick Bay
under the doctor's
supervision.
The rest of you keep
scanning the region.
Analyze this ship
from stem to stern.
Wherever he is,
find him. Come on.
Normally, I consider
a good night's sleep
an important part
of any health regimen,
but in this case,
I can't recommend it.
I respect your
medical opinion, doctor.
But at this point,
we're out of options.
This will regulate
your hypothalamus.
But in all probability,
I won't be able to wake you.
You'll be on your own.
I understand.
Ready?
Pleasant dreams.
Ah-koo-chee-moya.
Far from the sacred places
of my grandfathers,
far from the bones of my people,
I seek to sleep,
to meet the one who has
visited us in our dreams.
( door opens )
( door closes )
I know this is a dream--
my dream.
I'm in control.
You're mistaken.
Am I?
This is more
than a dream.
It's my reality
and you're no different
than the others.
"The others?"
The waking species.
For centuries,
you've come and found us
in a state that
you call "sleep"
and tried to destroy us,
but not anymore.
Now we are in control.
One by one,
you will fall asleep
and enter our reality,
where it is you who
will be destroyed.
We didn't attack you.
We didn't even
know you existed
until we started seeing
you in our dreams.
Tell me how
I can wake my crew
and I promise we'll leave.
As long as you're asleep,
you're no threat to us.
I can wake myself
anytime I want,
and if I do...
I'm going to start
looking for you
in the waking world--
find where you're sleeping.
You wouldn't want that.
Leave our space.
Once you're beyond it,
your people will awaken.
Just tell me how
far we need to go.
There's a six-planet system
less than a parsec away.
It marks the nearest border
of our space.
We can be past
it in one day.
Then wake yourself...
and pray you never
dream of us again.
Congratulations,
Commander.
You're awake.
( panting )
Chakotay.
I'm fine.
The alien-- did you see him?
And?
Well, it was certainly
one of the most interesting
away missions
I've ever been on.
I'll tell you about it
on the way to the Bridge.
Tuvok, scan
for a six-planet system.
It should be less
than a parsec from here.
I have it, Captain,
at coordinates 139 mark 42.
Tom, lay in a course.
Aye, Captain.
Course laid in.
Do you mind if I ask
where we're heading?
Past the aliens' territory.
Once we're clear of it, Harry
and the others should wake up.
And the rest of us
can finally get some sleep.
One step at a time, Tom.
From what the alien told me,
it sounds like they
have corporeal form,
but they communicate
through their dreams.
For them, it's as real
as the waking world.
Extraordinary.
It reminds me
of the Australian Aborigines.
They believed the dream world
was no more or less real
than the waking world.
In fact,
their creation mythology says
their ancestors actually dreamed
the universe into existence.
That's mythology.
This seems to be fact.
I wonder...
do they ever wake up?
How did they evolve this way?
We may never know.
Sometimes first contact
is last contact.
We're approaching the border
of the aliens' space.
Commander Tuvok,
inform the doctor.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
Wake up, Ensign.
( groaning softly )
What's going on?
You were napping.
In Sick Bay?
We had to move you here
when we couldn't wake you.
Whew.
How long?
17 hours.
I take it you
experienced nightmares
like the rest
of the crew.
Oh, I had nightmares, all right.
Tell me about them.
Well...
I was, uh, in the corridor...
( door opens )
Captain Janeway asked me
to bring you the results
of our astrometric scans.
She thought
they might be helpful
in determining the precise cause
of the crew's somnolence.
Thank you.
Ensign Kim,
now that you're awake,
I require your assistance
in Jefferies Tube 21-Beta.
Is something wrong?
No. I, um...
I'm still feeling
a little groggy.
Then, I'll wait
until you are fully recovered.
Now, then, Ensign,
you were telling me
about your nightmare.
You know what, doc? Um...
I'm... famished.
( clearing throat )
Haven't eaten
in at least 17 hours, right?
Very well.
Go eat, get some clothes on,
and report back in an hour.
I'll see you later.
You too, Seven.
And the next thing I knew,
I was being boiled alive
in a pot of my
own leola root stew.
Talk about a nightmare.
Well, it was
perfectly seasoned.
( door opens )
Well, if it isn't
Sleeping Beauty.
I do look well-rested, don't I?
NEELIX:
Is everyone
awake now?
The doc checked us all out
and says we're fine.
Have a seat.
We were just trading
dream stories.
Tell us yours.
Oh. It was...
nothing very interesting.
Just the usual...
You know, uh...
Who was she, Harry?
The woman of my dreams.
( cracking up )
What I'd like to know
is what Tuvok dreamt about.
Yes, Commander, tell us.
What do Vulcans dream?
Aren't you supposed
to have horrible nightmares?
I wonder what a Vulcan
nightmare would be like?
NEELIX:
Alone, exiled
on a planet
where the only form
of communication...
is laughter.
( all laughing )
Oh, come on, Tuvok.
I won't dignify this inquisition
with a response.
JANEWAY:
Red Alert.
All hands to battle stations.
They're coming around
for another pass.
Auxiliary power to the shields.
Return fire.
CHAKOTAY:
No damage to the alien ship.
Our phasers can't penetrate
their shields.
Arm photon torpedoes.
We seem to have a knack for
provoking strangers these days.
Shields are off-line.
Fire.
I've lost power
to the torpedo launchers.
What's happening?
Power is being drained
from all systems.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Captain.
Ensign Kim.
Commander Chakotay.
I'm glad to see you
all up and about.
Janeway to Engineering.
We need auxiliary power
to the engines now.
I think you'll find
that impossible.
B'Elanna, report.
TORRES: There's a localized
dampening field
around the ship, Captain.
I can't give you engines,
weapons, shields...
Everything you told me
was a lie.
This was all an elaborate trap
to get Voyager here.
It appears you're learning
more about my people after all.
Prepare to surrender your ship.
Captain, three more
alien vessels are approaching.
They are powering weapons.
You've gone to so much trouble
to commandeer this ship.
I don't think
you're going to destroy it.
I won't need to.
Janeway to the crew.
We're under attack.
Implement defense
procedure omega.
It's no use.
We've taken every deck.
The ship is ours.
Captain.
All the time I thought
I was negotiating,
they were just setting us up
to fly right into their web.
You couldn't have
known it was a trick.
I don't understand. They exist
in dreams and reality?
Apparently, entering our dreams
was their way
to learn about us...
perhaps to probe our weaknesses.
Not to mention lure
us into an ambush.
We need to retake the ship.
That means getting
out of this cargo bay.
I checked the Jefferies tubes.
They're sealed.
Maybe we can open them manually.
That's not going to be easy.
They've got people everywhere.
We'll have
to create a diversion.
Any ideas?
I have one, Captain.
( grunts )
What the hell are you doing?!
( speaking softly ):
Creating a diversion.
Ensign Kim,
it is your fault
we have been captured.
I suggest you fight back.
( grunting )
Tom...
try to get into
a Jefferies tube.
You two work on
the power grid.
I'll deal with this.
ALIEN: Stop, stop!
JANEWAY: What's going on here?
These are my people.
I'll handle them.
Ensign, that's enough.
Move!
What's wrong?
I'm still asleep.
What are you talking about?
Chakotay!
( alarmed gasp )
Commander Chakotay,
you're awake.
Am I?
Are you sure?
Of course you are.
What are you
looking for?
The moon.
What?
I don't see it.
Where's the Captain?
Asleep--
along with the rest of the crew.
All of them?
Except me.
No rest for the never-weary.
What happened?
As soon as you entered
your lucid dream,
they all began falling
asleep one by one.
I've been trying every method
I can think of to revive them,
but nothing works.
It's been 39 hours.
I've been asleep
for almost two days?
If I can't
wake them soon,
I'm going to have to start
feeding them intravenously.
They let me think I was awake,
but I was still dreaming.
You weren't
the only one.
Look at this.
What is it?
A neurogenic field
created by heightened
electrical activity
in the brain.
It's been occurring in all
the sleeping crew members--
and that's not all.
This is Ensign Kim's
brain wave pattern, indicating
that he's dreaming
in a hyper-REM state.
This is Crewman
Foster's pattern.
They're identical.
Lieutenant Torres,
Captain Janeway,
Commander Tuvok...
I don't know what it means.
I think I do.
Not only are they dreaming,
they're all having
the same dream.
It wasn't just my dream.
It was a communal dream.
Everyone's REM patterns
are identical.
They're experiencing
the same images,
each from his or her
own point of view.
Yes. I saw the rest
of the crew--
interacted with them.
We were all working together
to fight off an alien attack.
Which wasn't real.
Oh, we're under attack,
all right.
Commander?
Maybe this is the way these
aliens fight their enemies.
They exist somewhere in
our reality as physical beings,
but they must be asleep,
unable to defend themselves
against what they call
"waking species."
We'll never defeat them
in their dream reality,
but if we can find them,
find where they're sleeping,
we'll have the advantage.
But we've been scanning for
life-forms since this started
and we haven't found anything.
Maybe we've been looking
in the wrong place.
I'm betting a species that
spends its time sleeping
isn't going to be hanging around
where conventional scans
can locate them.
So, how do we find them?
This neurogenic
field you mentioned--
anyone in a hyper-REM state
would be producing one.
In theory, yes.
So if we scan
for other neurogenic fields,
it might lead us
to the sleeping aliens.
If you need me,
I'll be on the Bridge.
Time for a little energy boost,
Commander.
We don't want you drifting
back to sleep.
Sorry about the mess,
but this is what happens
when my repeated requests
for a larger Sick Bay
fall on deaf ears.
( console beeping )
What is it?
Scanners have detected
a neurogenic field
emanating from
beneath the surface of a planet
less than a light-year
from here.
Excuse me, Tom, but I've
got to change our course.
Still dreaming?
How is that possible?
I don't know, but that's
what Chakotay said
right before he vanished.
That doesn't make any sense.
He was wide awake
right here with us.
He said something
about still being asleep
and then he started tapping
the back of his hand
like he said he would
to wake up from his lucid dream.
( softly ):
And then he disappeared.
The question is,
where did he go?
The aliens must
have transported him somewhere.
Or perhaps he did wake up.
Tuvok?
It's possible he was dreaming
all of this.
Wait a minute.
If Chakotay was dreaming
and he woke up,
what are we doing here?
Perhaps we are dreaming
as well.
Now I'm lost.
You're not the only one.
Consider that we all
experienced nightmares
about an alien whose people
apparently live out their lives
in a dream state.
Perhaps we are in that state
this very moment.
That's ridiculous.
We're not asleep.
Wait.
When you dream, you're rarely
aware that you're sleeping.
I can understand
how we could mistake dreaming
for reality,
but that doesn't explain
how we're all interacting
with one another.
Maybe we're not.
Not what?
Interacting
with one another.
Maybe this is all
one person's dream--
if, for example, mine--
and none of you are really here.
Trust me, Neelix,
I wish I weren't, but I'm here.
Collective unconsciousness.
Seven, come here.
The Borg share
a collective consciousness.
These aliens
may have somehow induced
a state
of collective unconsciousness.
You mean... we're all
sharing the same dream?
TUVOK:
It is possible.
This is all
fascinating speculation,
but unless we have proof
to the contrary,
we have to treat this
like an invasion.
I managed to open
a Jefferies tube hatch.
Good work.
Neelix, Seven, Kim,
do what you can
to distract the guards.
We're going to find a way
to retake the ship.
Looks like a complete
power drain.
Their dampening field
has shut down the warp core.
Which begs the question
of what they intend to do
with an unpowered ship.
Tuvok, grab some phaser rifles
from the weapons locker.
Something tells me when we try
to disable the dampening field,
we're going to get
the aliens' attention.
It looks like they're using
harmonic inversion technology.
If I can isolate
the containment frequency,
I may be able to get
main power back on line.
( equipment powering up )
That was easy.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Warp core breach
in 60 seconds.
Maybe a little too easy.
I don't understand.
Can you eject the core?
I'm trying.
It's not working.
Warp core breach in 50 seconds.
( whooshing )
We've got to get
out of here.
I'm trying
to put a containment field
around Engineering.
Warp core breach in 40 seconds.
Got it! Let's move!
I don't understand why you
couldn't eject the core!
Warp core breach in 30 seconds.
Something's not right.
Captain, we must hurry!
I'm going back in there.
You'll be killed!
Warp core breach...
I think I'm onto something.
You two go!
Captain!
That's an order!
Warp core breach
in ten seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six...
( grunts )
five, four, three, two, one.
( explosion )
( breathing heavily )
Either I've become impervious
to antimatter explosions...
or we're still dreaming.
A warp core explosion
should have destroyed the ship.
If I were awake,
or if any of this were real,
which it obviously isn't.
Things just weren't adding up--
Chakotay's disappearance,
the warp core failing to eject.
And as Chakotay said,
"lucid dreaming
is about taking control"
so I... took a chance.
Surely, there must have been
a less extreme method
of testing your assumptions.
As Captain, you shouldn't be
taking chances with your life.
I'm touched
by your concern, Tuvok.
Now that we know
this is a dream...
what do we do?
I suggest we find a way
to regain consciousness.
Captain, how did
you wake yourself?
The same way you did.
The others?
They should all be
starting to wake up.
Rise and shine, Mr. Paris.
We need to get as far away
from their planet as possible.
Agreed.
I'll make the necessary
course correction.
What is it?
This isn't real.
Of course it is.
See?
No.
Doctor?
He's paranoid--
disoriented.
I suspect much
of the crew
will suffer similar
symptoms when they awake.
DOCTOR:
Try to relax, Commander.
I'm going to sedate you.
No! I need to wake up,
not sleep!
I'm here to help you.
No!
It's all right, Commander.
You're awake again.
What happened?
You dozed off.
I couldn't wake myself
like I did before.
Our proximity
to the neurogenic field
is making it more difficult
to stay conscious.
I need to get down there and
find a way to neutralize it.
Not so fast.
This is a highly potent
animazine derivative.
If you feel yourself falling
asleep again, you must use it.
And, Commander, I suggest
we keep an open com line.
I may need to provide you
with a verbal splash
of cold water
every now and then.
It's not working.
It's safe to assume that
Chakotay and the doctor
are making every effort
to wake us from our sleep.
We have to let the rest of
the crew know what's happening--
that as long as they know
they're in a dream,
they can't be harmed.
And if the aliens
try to stop us?
Then we turn this dreamworld
of theirs...
into a nightmare.
Okay, doctor...
I'm in.
Acknowledged, Commander.
Stand aside.
Your weapons are useless
against us.
You're not fooling anyone.
We know this is a dream.
You're confused.
Actually, I'm finally
seeing things clearly.
Shoot them.
Now, stand aside.
All of you, listen closely.
What we have to do
is stay in control
of the dream.
If we can do that,
the aliens shouldn't
be able to hurt us.
You sound very sure
of yourself, Captain.
Why shouldn't I be?
Have you thought
about what's happening
to your bodies
in the waking world?
How long do you think
they'll survive
without nourishment?
Without physical activity?
Your bodies are withering
away as we speak.
You can't stop it.
Don't be so sure.
It's some kind of transmitter.
It looks like they
use it to amplify
the neurogenic field.
Can you turn it off?
I tried knocking it out
with my phaser,
but there's some kind
of force field.
Commander?
I'm sorry.
I'm having trouble
concentrating.
Time for your medicine.
Doctor, this animazine--
it's pretty powerful.
Yes. And I suggest
you take it immediately.
These aliens...
they look pretty frail.
That's fascinating, Commander.
Now please inject yourself.
They probably wouldn't have
the same tolerance
for stimulants that we do.
What are you getting at?
The animazine might be capable
of waking up
one of these aliens.
Commander, I'd be
happy to discuss
comparative pharmacology
with you
after you administer
your injection.
Actually... I think
I'm going to give it
to one
of my sleepy friends here.
What would that accomplish?
If I can wake him up,
I might be able to get him
to deactivate this generator.
There's not enough animazine
for two doses.
If you fall asleep again,
there's no way I can revive you.
( sighing )
Doctor, I want you
to go to the Bridge.
Commander...
I'm giving you an order!
Go to the Bridge
and target my com signal
with a photon torpedo.
You're delirious.
You're asking me
to incinerate you.
Not just me...
these aliens...
and their transmitter, too.
But only if you
don't hear from me
in five minutes.
Understood?
Commander...
Understood?!
Aye, sir.
Tell me how to deactivate
this transmitter, or I shoot.
What happened?
Looks like he woke up.
I'll give you five seconds.
Four...
three...
two...
Chakotay.
Who's going to help
you now, Captain?
I found the cavern
and your people.
I'm there right now
in the waking world.
And it's all going
to be destroyed
in less than two minutes
unless you deactivate
that transmitter.
If you are there,
you'll be killed, too.
I think you're lying.
Oh, believe me,
if I don't contact my ship,
you and I are both
going to die in our sleep.
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
stardate 51471.3.
With the neurogenic field
neutralized,
I've been successful
in reviving the entire crew.
Unfortunately,
the experience has produced
a troubling side effect
for many of them--
acute insomnia.
( sighs )
Computer, lights on.
Sorry, Commander.
I didn't mean
to frighten you.
You're not starting breakfast
this early, are you?
Just rearranging
the supply cabinets.
I couldn't sleep.
Neither could I.
How about a soothing
cup of tea?
Sounds good.
I know it's silly,
but every time I'm
about to doze off,
I... become terrified
that I won't be able
to wake again.
( door opens )
You, too?
We just finished a little
late-night hoverball
on the holodeck.
Three games in a row.
We were hoping
it would wear us out.
You know, I could
learn to enjoy
these late-night
get-togethers.
Speak for yourself.
I would kill for
a good night's sleep.
Neelix, I think it's
time for breakfast.
( all chuckling )