( majestic theme playing )
Cold, patronizing,
arrogant...
I know
she can be difficult.
"Difficult"?
She's impossible.
I'm getting tired
of playing referee
every time you two
have a disagreement.
If you have a problem,
talk to her yourself.
Does the word "irrelevant"
mean anything to you?
She won't listen.
She may look human,
she may sound human,
but she's all Borg.
Part of the problem
is your attitude.
You've never tried
to accept Seven
as part of the crew.
And with good reason.
Guess what she
did this morning.
She took an isolinear
processor
out of Engineering
without asking,
and when I went
to Astrometrics to get it back,
she had locked the door.
Like that lab
is her own
private domain.
What do you want me to do?
Throw her in the brig
for the rest of the trip home?
I've heard worse ideas.
( on communicator ):
Seven of Nine to Chakotay.
Chakotay here.
Report to the Astrometrics Lab
at once.
On my way.
Did you hear that?
She's giving orders now.
I'm telling
you, Chakotay,
if she gets
in my way again,
I am not responsible
for what happens.
You're a senior officer
on this ship.
Act like one.
Find a way
to deal with her.
( scoffs )
Astrometrics?
I've been summoned.
Any guesses
what this is about?
None.
( computers beeping )
Your call
sounded urgent.
It was.
I've been working
to increase the range
of the astrometric
sensors,
and I've detected something
that you should find
of particular interest.
JANEWAY:
A ship. What's
special about it?
SEVEN:
I've analyzed
the warp signature.
It's a Starfleet vessel.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
The ship we're seeing is
in the Alpha Quadrant.
You couldn't
have extended
the astrometric
sensors that far.
No, but I increased
the range far enough
to detect a large network
of relay stations.
They are alien in origin,
abandoned,
but still functioning.
By establishing a sensor link
with the nearest station,
I'm getting readings
from the entire network.
The Starfleet ship
is within range
of one of the farthest sensors
near the outer edges
of the Alpha Quadrant.
It must be
on a deep-space mission.
I've extrapolated
its course.
It doesn't look
like we'll be able
to keep track
of it very long.
The ship should move
out of range in 41 minutes.
Can we use the network
to transmit a message?
Yes, but we'll have
to remodulate our signal
to match the network's
interlink frequency.
We don't have much time.
Get it done, Chakotay.
( console beeping )
( majestic theme playing )
Seven of Nine to Ensign Kim.
( on communicator ):
Kim here.
I'm sending you
the interlink frequencies.
Got it.
Seven, how much longer
do we have?
Sixteen minutes.
B'ELANNA:
That should do it. The sub-space
transceiver is at 200 percent
output and on line.
We're ready.
Open a channel.
Open.
Starfleet vessel...
this is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
We are in the Delta Quadrant
at coordinates
18 mark 205 mark 47.
Remodulate your signal to match
our interlink frequency.
We're receiving a transmission.
Let's hear it.
( static )
JANEWAY:
...Starship Voyager.
We are in the...
...at coordinates 18...
Bridge to Seven.
What went wrong?
( sighs )
I don't understand.
My readings show that the
station picked up our message
and relayed it
across the entire network.
We should try widening
the subspace bandwidth
and sending
the message again.
Do it.
Transmitting.
SEVEN:
The signal is being relayed.
No sign of interference.
( beeping )
Wait. It's being deflected
back again.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
...the Delta Quadrant
at coord...
SEVEN:
I have a possible
explanation, Captain.
As our carrier wave moves
along the network,
it may be degrading.
Oh. Can we try
a different kind of signal?
Something stronger?
A holographic datastream
might work.
It wouldn't degrade
so quickly.
It would take too long
to reconfigure the message.
Unless...
The doctor.
Exactly.
Bring him to Astrometrics
and I'll meet you there.
We don't have
much time.
( soft theme playing )
Doctor.
( sighs )
You have to come with me.
Quickly.
( sighs )
Would you mind at
least telling me
what all this is about?
When I requested
more away missions,
this isn't exactly
what I had in mind.
You may be our
only chance
to communicate
with that ship.
When you get there,
you'll be downloaded
into their EMH system.
I'm sending an initiation
code along with your program
so you'll be
activated immediately.
We have less
than 90 seconds
before that ship
moves out of range.
How am I supposed
to get back here?
When you've completed
your mission,
instruct them to move within
range of the sensor network.
With any luck, they'll be
able to send you back
the same way you came.
"Luck"?
I won't lie
to you, doctor.
A lot of things could go wrong.
We're relying
on an alien technology
to send you across thousands
of light-years.
So there's a chance
my program could be lost.
Yes. I'm asking you
to take that chance.
SEVEN:
Thirty-five seconds.
Doctor?
Far be it from me
to turn down
an opportunity
to become a hero.
I'm ready.
Torres to Bridge.
CHAKOTAY:
Standing by.
I'm downloading him
into the transceiver array.
SEVEN:
Ten seconds.
Good luck, doctor.
There's that word again.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hello? Is anyone here?
Computer, identify this ship.
COMPUTER:
This is the Federation
Starship Prometheus.
Are we in the Alpha Quadrant?
Affirmative.
Hmm.
Sickbay to Bridge.
All right, this is Sickbay
calling any crew member.
Please respond.
Computer, is the com system
malfunctioning?
Negative.
Then why can't I reach anyone?
Access to
the communications system
has been restricted.
Restricted?
But this is important.
Isn't there some sort of
emergency com channel availa--
( groans )
Try to lie still. You have
severe phaser burns.
What happened here?
( hoarsely ):
Romulans.
They've taken over the ship.
( groans )
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
Commander, there's
a vessel approaching
on an intercept course.
It's Starfleet.
I told you to mask
our warp trail.
I've been trying.
These new systems
are unfamiliar.
We should have left
some of the crew alive.
You'd be surprised
how stubborn humans can be.
The Starfleet ship
is closing.
Raise shields and prepare
to fire phasers.
( tricorder emits steady tone )
Computer, how many Romulans
are on board?
Twenty-seven.
Are there
any Starfleet crew members?
None alive.
Computer, display the design
schematic of this ship
and list general specifications.
USS Prometheus.
Experimental prototype
designed for deep-space
tactical assignments.
Primary battle systems
include regenerative shielding,
ablative hull armor,
multivector assault mode.
Multivector
assault mode? Describe.
Access to tactical data
requires level-4 clearance.
What can you show me
at my clearance level?
( rumbling )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Shields are holding.
Engage the multivector
assault mode.
That system has
never been tested.
Then we'll test it now.
( rumbling )
( computer beeps )
I gave you an order,
and I expect you to follow it.
Multivector assault mode now.
FEMALE:
Yes, Commander.
( alarm blaring )
COMPUTER:
Initiating decoupling sequence.
Auto-separation in ten seconds.
Nine, eight, seven...
Computer, what's happening?
Six, five...
Computer?
Four, three...
Two, one.
Separation sequence
in progress.
( dramatic theme playing )
We're in attack
formation.
Each section
is armed
and responding
to our command.
( rumbling )
( screams )
Attack pattern beta-four-seven.
Specify target.
The Starfleet vessel,
bearing 162 mark 7.
Pattern and target confirmed.
I think we should consider that
a successful test.
Begin the reintegration
sequence.
Then get me
a full damage report.
Yes, Commander.
( male groaning )
He's hurt.
Take him to the medical bay.
Reintegration sequence
complete.
Computer, is there any way
for me to gain access
to the communication system
to send a message
to another ship?
Negative.
Communications access requires
level-4 clearance or above.
( door opens )
( footsteps approaching )
( groaning )
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Who activated you?
You did.
Automatically, when
you entered Sickbay.
Can you treat him?
Of course.
That's my function.
Third-degree burns,
hairline jaw fracture
and a ruptured blood
vessel in his brain.
I'll have to operate.
You're a Starfleet program.
Why should
I trust you?
I'm a doctor.
Whether my patient
is human or Romulan,
I'll do everything
in my power to save him.
You're welcome to assist me
if you'd like.
Or maybe you'd just prefer
to supervise.
Report to me
when you're finished.
Mm-hmm.
( door opens and closes )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Computer, can I access
this ship's EMH program
or do I need some kind
of clearance for that, too?
Access to that program
is unrestricted.
Activate it.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
What the hell are you doing
in my Sickbay?
I've been programmed to identify
every member of this crew.
You aren't one of them.
That's because I'm...
State your rank
and security clearance.
I don't have clearance.
I'm an Emergency
Medical Hologram.
I've been sent here to...
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
You're the Mark-1 EMH.
The inferior program.
Inferior?
Beady eyes, terrible bedside
manner. I recognize you.
But you're not part
of this database.
What are you doing here?
If you disengage
your vocal subroutines
for one second,
I'd explain.
I was transmitted
onto this ship
by a Starfleet vessel over
60,000 light-years from here.
60,000 light-years?
We don't have ships
that far out.
It's the Starship Voyager.
We were taken
into the Delta Quadrant
four years ago
by an alien force...
What are you doing?
Activating intruder alert.
That's the last thing
you want to do.
Securit--
Listen to me!
This vessel has been
taken over by Romulans.
The crew is dead.
You and I are the only
Starfleet officers on board.
Do you understand?
( muffled agreement )
Computer, deactivate EMH.
Computer, activate EMH.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
Now what?
I need your help!
Starfleet Security Protocol
28, Subsection D:
"In the event of
hostile alien takeover,
"the EMH is to deactivate
and wait for rescue."
I'm afraid you don't
have that luxury.
There are two ships at stake
here. Yours and mine.
Now, I need to know more
about what's happening.
Is the Federation at war
with the Romulans?
No. The Romulans
haven't gotten involved
in our fight with the Dominion.
The who?
Long story.
In any case, we need to take
control of this situation.
I'm a doctor,
not a commando.
It's time you became
a little of both.
You don't understand. The
Prometheus
is an experimental
prototype, and so am I.
I... I... I haven't even
been field-tested yet.
I'm not designed
for this kind of duty.
( gasps )
Try to calm down.
You'll do fine as
long as I'm here.
I have plenty of expertise
in this area.
Now, first things first.
We've got a patient.
You treat his burns.
I'll repair the bone fracture.
You're not serious.
I certainly am.
He's the enemy.
He needs our help.
I assume you're familiar
with the Hippocratic Oath?
You see? You see
what's happening.
The Romulans
are using you.
Hmm.
Hmm, what?
Your holo-matrix
is unstable.
It may explain
your erratic behavior.
I told you, I'm a
work in progress.
I was only installed
six weeks ago.
Stable or not, I need you,
and so does he.
He'll live.
I say we leave him and
deactivate ourselves.
No!
You're free
to do as you please.
Go cower inside the data
processor if you'd like.
I'll work alone.
We're medical holograms.
What can we
expect to do
against a ship
full of Romulans?
I'm not sure. Not yet.
But I've faced
my share of challenges.
Alien invasions,
macroviral infestations.
I've crossed Borg space,
traveled through time.
Have you run
a self-diagnostic lately?
The EMH-1 is designed
to function in Sickbay only.
Voyager lost its Chief Medical
Officer four years ago.
I've been active ever since.
Four years?
No wonder you're delusional.
Your program's degrading
after being active for so long.
I assure you I am
in perfect health.
I was saving Voyager
from annihilation
when you were only a gleam
in your programmer's eye.
Now are you going to help me
take back this ship or not?
Get me
the thrombic modulator.
DOCTOR:
Hmm. Ah.
Hmm?
It's the cone-shaped device.
Hand it to me, please.
Medical science has
made a few advances
while you've
been off in the...
Delta Quadrant,
did you say?
That's right.
We don't use scalpels
or leeches anymore.
I suggest you
let me handle
the medical side
of things.
As for retaking the ship,
I'll leave that in
your experienced hands.
( computer beeps )
( light theme playing )
( sighs )
( console beeping )
No word.
Our link to the sensor net
is stable.
Seven of Nine is standing
watch in Astrometrics.
I tried
to relieve her,
but she doesn't want
to leave her post.
She says she doesn't
need to regenerate
for the next few days.
What are you doing?
Letters home.
I started them a year ago.
One to my family...
one to Mark.
I'm making a few updates
just in case.
I know.
It's premature.
You're right.
It's probably
a mistake for us
to get our hopes
up at all.
We've been through
this before.
All right,
I'll admit it.
I just finished a letter
to my cousin in Ohio.
( both chuckle )
( both groaning )
( door opens )
Doctor is in.
Lieutenant, thank
God you're here.
What seems to be
the trouble?
Well, one minute, they
were eating lunch,
and the next, they
started perspiring
and complaining
of chest pain.
Hmm, no wonder.
Acute functional dyspepsia.
What's that?
Heartburn.
Oh, I'm terribly
sorry.
I don't know how this
could have happened.
I'll replicate
some antacid.
We'll have you feeling
better in no time.
They're going to be
all right, aren't they?
It's heartburn, Neelix,
not the Terrellian plague.
What did you feed
them anyway?
"Rodeo Red's Red Hot,
Rootin' Tootin' Chili."
( laughs )
Where did you find
that recipe?
I've been brushing up on
classic American cuisine.
When we get back to Earth,
I want to make sure I have
marketable
job skills.
Don't you think you're
jumping the gun a little bit?
The doctor is going
to make it back,
and he's going to bring a plan
for Starfleet to rescue us.
I have complete
confidence in him.
I hope you're right.
If not, I'm going to spend
the rest of this trip
treating upset stomachs.
Oh, believe me,
this is never going
to happen again.
It's just a matter of
perfecting the recipe.
Next time, I'll use
a few less chilapenos.
( light theme playing )
I've accessed the
navigational logs.
We're at warp 9.9.
Heading straight
for Romulan space.
This vessel was designed
to go faster than anything
in the fleet,
so we'll never be rescued.
We've got to find a way
to turn this ship around.
How? Waltz onto the Bridge
and take over the helm?
Refresh my memory.
Which of us has
the terrible bedside manner?
You're not my patient.
My first bit of good news.
We have to incapacitate
the Romulans somehow.
What kind of anesthetics
do you have handy?
Only the best.
Axonol, neurozine,
anesthezine.
Neurozine will do nicely.
It can be distributed
in gaseous form.
Show me a schematic of the
ship's ventilation system.
Please.
( computer beeping )
All primary systems have
been rerouted to the Bridge,
including
environmental control.
It looks like there are
holo-emitters on every deck.
There are.
Unlike you, I'm not
condemned to a Sickbay.
Get three canisters
of neurozine.
As a matter of record,
I have free rein on Voyager
and I can even leave
the ship as well.
Leave your ship? How?
My mobile emitter.
A little piece
of 29th-century
technology we obtained.
Really?
I'm as close
to a sentient life-form
as any hologram
could hope to be.
I socialize with the crew,
fraternize with aliens.
I've even had
sexual relations.
Sex?
How's that possible?
We're not equipped--
Let's just say,
I made an addition
to my program.
Before you leave,
maybe you could
download those subroutines
into my database.
We'll see.
( beeping )
It looks like
the only place
I can access
environmental control
is from the Ops console
on the Bridge.
The Bridge is swarming
with Romulans.
That's the first
thing you learn
in the real world--
think on your feet.
Well, good luck then.
Computer, deactivate--
Not so fast.
You're going
to Jefferies Tube 17.
The moment I unlock
the controls,
you release the gas
into the ventilation system.
Jefferies Tube 17?
That's five decks up.
What if I run
into Romulans?
Improvise.
Your journey begins here.
Traditionally,
one crawls in headfirst.
Thanks.
ROMULAN:
There you are, doctor.
Have you completed
the surgery?
Yes. Your friend
is recovering nicely.
However, I found something
disturbing in his blood work.
It seems he's been exposed
to a nasty strain
of the Torothka virus,
and if he was, you
may all have been.
I've come to run
some scans.
No one here is sick.
Not yet.
I understand the stomach
cramps are unbearable,
although some say
the rash is worse.
Conduct your scans.
( device humming )
How far are we from our border?
At our present
velocity, 40 minutes.
Alter our heading
to 118 mark 26.
That will take us
off our course to Romulus.
There's been
a change of plans.
We're giving this ship
to someone
who will make use
of its full potential--
the Tal Shiar.
I've made arrangements
to rendezvous
with their fleet
within the hour.
ROMULAN:
But, Commander, they're
expecting us--
COMMANDER:
You have your orders.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What are you doing?
I'm checking the biofilters
for evidence of the virus.
You haven't taken
any readings at all.
Hmm.
( device humming )
Next time...
order the chicken salad.
( door opens )
Oh! Am I glad to see you.
What's the emergency?
Ah. Take a look
around you, Harry.
What do you see?
Sickbay?
Exactly.
So?
So, it's not the helm
of a starship, is it?
Did you accidentally
inject yourself
with some kind
of psychotropic agent?
I am a pilot, Harry,
not a doctor.
This is a temporary
assignment--
just till the doc gets back.
What if he doesn't
get back?
He'll be back.
I need your help, Harry.
Rescue me from
medical exile.
How?
( sighs )
You're an expert
in holo-technology.
You have got to
design a new doctor.
( snickers )
You really are delirious.
It took the greatest
holo-engineers in Starfleet
years to develop the EMH.
I can't just design
a new doctor.
( sighs )
Think of it
as a challenge, Harry--
a chance to make history
and save your best friend
all at the same time.
Lieutenant Torres.
( computers beeping )
You are recalibrating
the relay interface.
That's right.
State your reasons for
making these modifications.
"State your reasons,
please."
It's not what
you say, Seven.
It's how you say it.
I don't understand.
( sighs )
You may have noticed
that some of the crew
seem a bit...on edge
when you're around.
I was Borg.
I elicit apprehension.
No, that's not what I mean.
We're not afraid that you're
going to assimilate us.
We're just not used to...
You just...
You're rude.
I am rude.
Yes. Yes. You order
people around.
You do things
without permission.
and whether
you realize it or not,
you come off
as a little insulting.
You don't even say
"please" or "thank you."
Look, I don't expect you
to change overnight, but...
try to remember
that we are not just
a bunch of drones.
( computer beeping )
Your attempt
to recalibrate
the interface
is ill-advised.
The risk of disrupting
our link is too great.
In your opinion.
That is exactly
what I'm talking about.
You haven't even been
listening to me.
I don't know why I try to talk
to you if you don't even...
( staticky fritzing )
Are we losing the link?
No. We're receiving
a transmission
from the relay station.
The doctor?
( suspenseful theme playing )
What are you?
I'm Lieutenant Torres
of the Starship Voyager.
You are using our technology.
You mean
the sensor network?
We thought
that it was abandoned.
It belongs to the Hirogen.
Terminate your link.
No, no, wait, please.
We just...
The link has
been severed.
What else have you
done to this ship?
I will deactivate you
unless you start
answering my questions.
If I answer them,
you'll very likely
deactivate me anyway,
so I fail to
see the point.
You are nothing
but a computer-generated
projection.
I find it hard to believe
you're capable of taking
these actions independently.
How flattering.
Tell me who is
operating your program.
Is it someone
on this ship?
A Starfleet crew
member we missed
or one of my own men?
Paranoia is a way of life
for you, isn't it?
( door opens )
The computer log shows
the ship received an optronic
datastream transmission
approximately six hours ago.
It contained
a holographic subroutine.
Who sent it?
Unknown. The data pattern
had a Starfleet signature.
So, Starfleet has managed
to sneak a holographic
operative aboard.
Very clever.
Were you only sent
to spy on us,
or does your mission
include sabotage?
( sighs )
The datastream
you detected
came from an alien
sensor network.
It transferred me
from a Starfleet ship
in the Delta Quadrant.
The Delta Quadrant?
That's absurd.
This is pointless.
I couldn't agree more.
Maybe there's a better way
to retrieve information
from a hologram.
I suggest a complete
algorithm extraction.
We can analyze
his subroutines one by one.
Proceed.
( computer beeping )
Isn't there some kind
of convention
regarding the treatment
of prisoners?
( Romulans gasping
and coughing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Did it work?
Sorry to interrupt.
Did you anesthetize
the entire ship?
I did, I did.
How did you manage
to release the neurozine?
I never opened
the ventilation system.
Trapped in
the Jefferies tube,
alone, nowhere to run,
his smug comrade
captured by Romulans,
EMH-2 had to improvise.
Inspiration. He
accessed the main computer
and simulated a shipwide
biohazard, making the
computer think there was
a microbiotic contamination
on all decks.
And the ventilation system
opened automatically.
Presto. He then crawled
back out of the tube,
accessed the holo-emitters,
transferred here,
excused the Romulan,
saw the dumbfounded look
on his comrade's face...
The end.
You know, you really should
keep a personal log.
Why bore others needlessly?
( sighs )
We have to get to the Bridge.
This ship needs a crew,
and we're it.
Oh. Trouble.
The Prometheus is
a prototype-- top secret.
Only four people
in all of Starfleet were
trained to operate it.
I hope
your myriad adventures
included piloting lessons
because there's nothing
in my program
that will help us
fly this thing.
I've had my share of
piloting experience.
Actually...
only two lessons
and they were in
a shuttlecraft...
on the holodeck,
but I showed
great intuition.
Where's the helm?
You'd better intuit
it fast.
We're only about eight minutes
from the Romulan border.
Ah, there it is.
EMH-2:
This is all very...
complicated.
Stop breathing
down my neck.
My breathing is
merely a simulation.
So is my neck.
Stop it anyway.
Is this
a thruster control?
Don't touch that.
We don't know what it does.
It could be
the self-destruct.
You look worried.
I'm just...concentrating.
You don't know
what you're doing, do you?
This is not a shuttle
and we are not on a holodeck.
Shh.
Mr. "I can
leave my ship."
The voice
of experience.
Let me think.
Ah, here it is.
This looks like
the nacelle power control.
So? So?
There's a little trick
I saw Mr. Paris do once.
If I can generate
a slight overload
to the nacelle coils,
it'll collapse the warp field.
( both grunting )
What happened?
I did it. We've stopped.
Ah. All we have to
do now is find a way
to send Starfleet
a distress signal and...
( shrill beeping )
Beep-beep-beep.
Beep-beep-beep?
I've never heard
that one before.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Oh, no.
What?
I'm not sure, but I
think whatever I did
initiated a warp
core overload.
You mean the ship's
going to explode?
You've got to stop it.
( beeping stops )
Ah. No problem.
( strident beeping )
What now?
Unless I'm mistaken,
and for once, I
sincerely hope I am,
there are three
Romulan warbirds
on an intercept course.
( suspenseful theme calming )
We're boosting the signal gain
as high as it'll go.
I think we can cut through
the alien's jamming signal.
ALIEN:
I warned you.
JANEWAY:
I apologize
for our intrusion.
Allow me to explain.
No explanations.
Your relay network
gave us the unique opportunity
to communicate with our people.
They are very far away,
and we're expecting
a message back from them.
All messages
will be intercepted.
( beeping )
He's trying to jam
the link again.
There must be some room
for negotiation.
Isn't there anything you might
accept in exchange for...?
( screaming )
What happened?
I generated
a feedback surge
along our sensor link.
You killed him?
It was a mild shock.
He will recover.
And when he does?
He wasn't responding
to diplomacy.
Is the sensor link stable?
( console beeping )
Yes, Captain.
Keep watching for the doctor.
Let me know if our friend
gives us any more trouble.
( suspenseful theme playing )
"Mild shock."
( door opens and closes)
Not bad.
Thank you.
( beeping )
There. I finished inputting
the doctor's physical
characteristics.
Let's have a look.
Computer, activate
the Emergency
Medical Hologram
Replacement Program.
( computer beeps )
Do you think
we should give him
a little more hair?
What do you say we try
to get him working first,
then we can worry
about personal grooming.
Right. You're the boss.
What do we do next?
I've downloaded
the ship's entire
medical library and compressed
it into a single data file.
It's got all the classics
from Gray's Anatomy
to Leonard McCoy's
Comparative Alien Physiology.
And once we transfer
all the data
into stone face's matrix,
we'll have ourselves
a brand-new medical expert.
That's what I'm hoping.
Harry, you are a genius.
Don't congratulate me yet.
This is only the first step.
PARIS:
Yeah, but it's a step
in the right direction.
I'm telling you, this probably
isn't going to work.
What happened
to all that youthful optimism?
Being a doctor is a lot more
than knowing the facts.
We still have to create
analytical subroutines
to help him diagnose patients,
tactile protocols,
so he can perform surgery,
not to mention
a personality profile.
Oh, you know, I've been
thinking about that.
Maybe we should make this one
a little more...pleasant
than the old doc.
All right. I'm ready
to transfer the data.
Computer, transfer
medical library master file
to Emergency Medical
Replacement Hologram.
COMPUTER:
Transfer complete.
Chapter one: The Animal Cell.
"All the tissues of the body
originate from a microscopic
structure, the fertilized ovum,
which consists of a soft,
jelly-like material
enclosed in a membrane
and containing a..."
What's he doing?
"...or small spherical body
inside..."
I think he's reciting
Gray's Anatomy.
"This may be regarded
as a complete cell."
Can you stop him?
I'm trying.
"...in nature,
but differing in external form."
Paragraph.
Listen, this is all
very fascinating...
"In the higher organisms...
but would you please
be quiet for a minute?
KIM:
He doesn't have speech
recognition protocols yet.
Well, give him some, would you?
"...similar to that
found in the ovum
and usually called cytoplasm..."
What's happening?
It's an overload.
His matrix can't
accommodate all the data.
"Contain no nuclei..."
( groans )
( computer beeping )
( sighs )
What are you doing?
I'm downloading Gray's Anatomy
chapter by chapter.
I thought you said
it was too much data
for his holo-matrix
to handle.
It's not for the EMH.
It's for you.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The Romulan vessels
are closing in.
Two minutes to intercept.
Get us out of here!
I can't get
this ship moving.
Try rerouting power
to the impulse engines.
Reroute power,
reroute power.
Here we go.
I think I found
the relay controls.
Hey, I'm finally getting
the hang of this.
( static )
What's happening?
Sorry. I must have
transferred power
from the holo-emitters.
Well, be more careful.
If I'm deactivated,
this ship will never
get back to Starfleet.
Okay, I'm taking power
from life support.
We don't need that.
Try engines now.
( beeping denial )
Nothing.
Why isn't this working?
Thirty seconds
to intercept.
They're right on top of us.
Hold it. I see
the problem.
The thrust initiator
is off-line.
Stand by.
Fifteen seconds.
They're charging weapons!
See if you can access
the shields.
I said...
I said shields!
Already done. Shields up.
MALE:
This is the warbird T'Met
calling the Prometheus.
Commander Rekar...respond.
Commander.
( deep voice ):
This is the Prometheus.
Activate your viewscreen.
Our viewscreen is
not operational.
We've had some trouble
with Starfleet commandos.
Where's Rekar?
In the medical bay.
He suffered minor injuries.
Identify yourself.
( whispers ):
You first.
Repeat your last statement.
I don't understand.
State your identity.
This is Sub-Commander Almak.
Lower your shields
and prepare to be boarded.
They're already down.
Maybe there's
something wrong
with your
sensor readings.
You'd better not
try to transport
until we can be
sure it's safe.
Lower your shields immediately,
or I'll open fire.
Immediately?
Yes. Prometheus out.
( rumbling )
( both grunt )
Direct hit.
Shields down to 20 percent.
( computer beeping )
Three more ships
are approaching.
We're doomed.
( rumbling )
No.
They're Starfleet.
What are they doing?
Firing on us.
They must think
Romulans are on board.
They're right!
( dramatic theme swelling )
( dramatic theme playing )
Prometheus to any
Starfleet vessel. Respond.
Prometheus...
It's no use.
They can't hear us.
The Romulans have scrambled
the com frequencies.
( console beeping )
Doctor, some...thing
just went off-line.
Specifically?
The secondary
gyrodyne relays
in the propulsion field
inter-matrix have depolarized.
In English.
I'm just reading
what it says here.
I'll try to
stabilize the ship.
Transfer auxiliary power
to the maneuvering
thrusters.
Transferring
auxiliary power now.
Good work, Mark-2.
Thanks.
You'd better get to tactical.
We're going to have
to defend ourselves.
Tactical. Right.
What are you
waiting for? Shoot.
Shoot!
There are so many controls.
Find the one that says "fire"
and push it!
It's not working. It says here
the phasers are off-line.
Well, then fire a torpedo!
( dramatic theme playing )
You hit the wrong ship.
It wasn't my fault.
Well, then, whose fault was it,
the torpedo's?
You're supposed
to tell it what to do.
( yells )
Navigational control
is off-line.
Everything is off-line--
weapons, shields...
It gets worse.
There are two warbirds
coming right at us.
My brilliant existence
cut short...
No time to explore
the universe...
no time to smell the roses...
no time for...sex.
COMPUTER:
Initiating decoupling sequence.
What's that?
What have I done now?
Auto-separation in 10 seconds.
Auto-separation?
I think the Romulans
did this before.
How do we turn it off?
I don't think we can.
...Five, four, three, two...
If I recall correctly,
this next part gets
a little bumpy.
Separation sequence
in progress.
( dramatic theme playing )
Hold on. Unh.
Specify attack pattern.
Attack pattern...alpha?
Specify target.
Romulans!
( dramatic theme playing )
Bull's-eye!
The warbirds
are in retreat.
Doctor,
we've done it!
Two holograms alone.
Romulans on one side.
Starfleet on the other.
Alarms beeping
everywhere.
EMH-2. Newborn but
filled with courage.
EMH-1. Armed with
years of experience.
Together, they
emerged triumphant.
The end.
( shrill beeping )
Or not.
( whoosh of active transport)
Welcome to the Prometheus,
gentlemen.
It's about time.
( calm theme playing )
I'm receiving
a transmission
through the sensor network.
Origin...
the Alpha Quadrant.
Does it contain
a holographic subroutine?
Yes.
Transfer it
to Sickbay.
Torres to Bridge.
Captain, I think he's back.
( staticky buzzing )
Doctor...
report.
I-- I did it.
You completed the mission?
Yes. Once the Romulans
were out of the way.
Romulans?
They'd taken over
the Prometheus.
The ship I was on.
But I managed
to turn the tables on them
with a little help
from a fellow EMH.
You got through
to Starfleet?
I spoke directly
with Headquarters.
Apparently, Voyager was
declared officially lost
14 months ago.
I set the record straight.
I told them everything
that's happened to this crew.
They said they would
contact your families
to tell them the news
and promised
that they won't stop
until they've found a way
to get Voyager back home.
And they asked me
to relay a message.
They wanted you to know...
you're no longer alone.
( sweet theme playing )
60,000 light-years
seems a little closer today.
( majestic theme playing )