( crackling static )
MAN ( garbled ):
This is... ( static )
...to the USS Voyager.
If you are receiving
this message...
please... it carefully.
We have... ( static )
This is Starfleet...
...receiving this message...
( crackling static )
This is Starfleet Command...
( garbled voice )
( garbled message continues )
...this message, study...
carefully.
We have...
( message cuts off )
What happened?
KIM:
I'm not sure.
The transmission
just... stopped.
Locate the source.
See if you can
get it back.
It looks like...
Captain,
the transmission was sent
along the same network
of alien relay stations
we used to send the Doctor
to the Alpha Quadrant.
Starfleet Command must be
using them just like we did.
Harry, can you clear the
interference from that message?
Yes, ma'am.
They said they
wouldn't stop
until they found
a way to get us home.
TUVOK:
Nonetheless, we can't assume
they've been able to devise
a plan this quickly.
They're communicating with us.
That's a big step.
Okay, I've reprocessed
everything we received.
I've cleared out most
of the interference. Here it is.
This is Starfleet Command
to the USS Voyager.
If you are receiving
this message,
please study it carefully.
We have information...
KIM:
That's all we got.
It looks like the bulk
of the transmission
is lodged in one
of the relay stations.
Can you tell
which one?
It's about 3.8
light-years from us
on a heading of 274 mark 13.
Set a course, Tom.
Last time we used one
of those stations,
the people who built
it weren't too happy.
We'll deal with that
if we have to,
but I'm not going to lose
this opportunity.
We're going to find out what
the rest of that message says.
( staticky ):
This is ... Command
to the USS Voyager.
If you are
receiving this message,
please study it carefully...
Who sent this message?
Unknown.
It comes from across the galaxy.
Locate the ship receiving it.
It's on a course
to one of our modules.
Intercept.
( sighs )
Maybe they've figured out
a way to get us home.
How could they
get us home
from 60,000
light-years away?
Who knows what
technological advances
Starfleet has come up with
since we've been gone?
They might have developed
a whole new way
of traveling through space.
Since it was technology
that brought us
to the Delta Quadrant
in the first place,
it's a reasonable assumption
technology
could bring us back again.
Starfleet found
a stable wormhole
to the Gamma Quadrant.
Maybe they've discovered
one that leads here.
This kind of speculation can be
intriguing, but be careful
about setting yourselves up
to be disappointed.
I'm just happy my folks
know I'm alive.
I imagine there were
quite a few celebrations
when people got the news.
Probably, but I can see
where it might make things
more difficult for some.
I'd guess a lot of people
had given up on us--
done their mourning,
gone on with their lives--
found some kind
of resolution.
Now they get word
that we're alive,
but so far away that we
might as well be dead.
Some people might feel that way,
but not my mom and dad.
At the very least, we know
the relay stations extend
almost all the way
to the Alpha Quadrant.
If Starfleet has found a way to
use them to transmit messages,
we'll be able to stay
in constant contact
with people at home.
That has
to be comforting.
Sure it is, but I think
it's more comforting
to think that Starfleet
is going to get us home.
If no one objects,
that's what I'm going to do.
You were supposed to report
to Sick Bay this morning
for your weekly checkup.
Where have you been?
Here, doing my job.
And just what is
this pressing task?
I'm trying to retrieve
more of the message
transmitted
from Starfleet Command.
Hmm. Your devotion
to duty is admirable,
but you must remember
that your implants
have to be
monitored regularly.
I'm fine.
No, you're not.
I'm detecting
reduced levels
of erythrocytes
in your blood.
How long has it been
since you regenerated?
58 hours.
Well, that explains it.
We've discussed
this before, Seven.
You must regenerate
in your alcove
for at least
three hours a day.
I have gone as long as 200 hours
without regenerating.
That was when
you were a Borg.
You seem to forget you're
a good deal more human now.
I assure you,
I have not forgotten.
( console beeping )
Another one.
I beg your pardon?
I've retrieved
another word of text.
That makes six.
Six words in 58 hours?
Wouldn't it be
more efficient just to wait
until we arrive
at the relay station?
This message is important
to the Captain.
I'm aware of that.
In fact, if it weren't
for me, this transmission
wouldn't have been possible
in the first place.
I was the one
who risked my matrix
in order to go
to the Alpha Quadrant.
If we ever get home,
I expect I'll become
quite the hero.
"Emergency Medical
Hologram instrumental
in the return
of Voyager crew."
Has a nice ring to it,
don't you think?
On the other hand, it
is entirely possible
that your program
will be deleted
and you'll be
upgraded to conform
to the most
recent standards.
Unlikely.
I've accomplished things
no EMH ever has.
In fact, most likely
I'll become
an object of intense
study and discussion--
possibly even veneration.
( rumbling )
What's that?
Report.
We're encountering some kind
of gravimetric forces.
Source?
Looks like it's coming
from the relay station
we're heading for.
That station is still
two light-years away.
How could it project
a gravimetric field this far?
CHAKOTAY:
It'd have to have an incredibly
powerful energy source.
I've compensated
for the disturbance.
We should be all right--
at least until
we get closer.
TUVOK:
I'm detecting a ship, Captain.
800,000 kilometers
off the port bow.
On screen.
TUVOK:
It's adrift.
No propulsion systems,
no weapons, no life support.
KIM:
I'm picking up one
male humanoid aboard.
He's dead.
As soon as we're close enough,
beam the body to Sick Bay.
I want to know how he died.
What's happened to him?
He appears to have suffered
a complete osteotomy.
He's been gutted.
Apparently, some kind of
surgical procedure was used
to remove
the entire skeleton,
as well as the musculature,
the ligaments and tendons,
and the internal organs.
How long ago did this happen?
It's difficult to say.
Somewhere between
a week and a month.
I've seen this before.
The Borg encountered
a small ship of Species 5174.
They were also destroyed
in this fashion.
Did you ever determine
who did it and why?
No, it was irrelevant.
Return the body to his ship.
His people may be able
to retrieve him.
Very well.
When we get closer
to the station,
we can use the data
processors in Astrometrics
to download the message.
Yes, Captain.
Captain's Log,
stardate 51501.4.
After two days at high warp,
we're close enough
to the relay station
to see it on long-range
visual sensors.
PARIS:
Not exactly what I expected.
It looks ancient.
Radiometric decay ratios
indicate
it's at least
100,000 years old.
Scan for life-forms.
Negative, sir.
Looks like there's
nobody home.
Well, that's good news.
( rumbling )
Here we go again.
TUVOK:
The gravimetric field.
KIM:
Commander,
if my sensors
are right, that
station is using
a quantum singularity
as a power source.
A black hole?
It's a tiny
one, probably
about a centimeter
in diameter,
but it's
putting out
almost four terawatts
of energy.
Then someone has managed
to contain a singularity,
construct a space station
around it and tap its power.
That's fascinating.
Can we take this ship
any closer?
I wouldn't
recommend it.
Voyager would take a beating
from the gravimetric eddies.
All right, Tom,
back us off.
Aye, sir.
Bridge to Janeway.
Go ahead.
We're as close as we're
going to be able to get.
Okay. We'll see if we can
download the message from here.
The datastream degraded
during transmission.
Elements have been
dislocated, rearranged.
It's going to require some time
to decompress the message
and rearrange it in
the proper sequence.
Don't worry
about the sequence.
Get it out in bits and pieces
if you have to.
We can put it
together later.
I've accessed
a block of data.
I'm downloading
the text.
"How much we miss you...
"We talk about you often...
wondering about your... day."
It sounds awfully personal
from Starfleet Command.
"The children have grown
so much you wouldn't... "
These are letters.
These are letters from home.
You'll be the official
mail carrier, Neelix.
We'll get you the letters as
quickly as we can download them.
A task I'm happy
to perform, Captain.
I can tell you, I've never
seen the crew this excited.
This is as close
as they've come
to their families
in almost four years.
I promise to treat
these like gemstones.
By the time you've
delivered them,
we should have more.
Captain.
I've discovered something odd.
There seems to be more
here than just letters.
What do you mean?
There's a latent datastream
buried under the message.
It's heavily encrypted.
Encrypted?
It appears to contain
a large block of text
and what may be maps.
Can you retrieve any of it?
Not immediately.
When more of the letters
have been cleared out,
I should be able to
access the coded message.
Well... I might just hope
that it contains a plan
for bringing us back
to the Alpha Quadrant.
I'm curious, Seven.
What do you think
about all this?
Messages, the possibility
of getting home?
It lacks any emotional
resonance for me.
I've never even
been to Earth.
You realize you may
have family there.
That had not occurred to me.
You could have cousins,
grandparents...
There might be more emotional
resonance than you think.
( clears throat loudly )
I am happy to announce
that I have the first
letters from home.
Who are they for,
Neelix?
Uh, this one is addressed
to Commander Chakotay.
Who's it from, Commander?
An old friend...
the person who recruited
me into the Maquis.
Maybe I'll read this
in private.
Tom, you have the Bridge.
Neelix, wait a minute.
Aren't there any more?
No. No more
for the Bridge crew.
Not yet.
Be patient.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Good news, Mr. Vulcan.
This one's for you.
Thank you, Mr. Neelix.
You can put it
on the desk.
Was there
something more?
Aren't you going
to read it?
Of course.
I-I mean, aren't you
going to read it now?
I'm finishing my weekly
tactical review.
When it's completed
I'll read the message.
You're going to wait
until you've finished
the tactical review?
Do you have any
reason to believe
the content of the message
will change during that time?
Well, that's
not the point.
It's a letter
from your family.
Don't you want to know
what it says?
I fully intend to
find out what it says.
It has some important news.
You mean you've read it?
Well, only the first few lines.
When I was seeing
who it was addressed to,
I... I couldn't help it.
I-I... would you like me
to read it to you?
Very well.
"My husband, we have
been given the news
"that you are alive.
"Your children and I
"have asked the priests
at the Temple of Aymonk
to say prayers
for your safe return."
That's very sweet.
Amonak.
Pardon?
The Temple of Amonak--
one of the most
sacred on Vulcan.
Amonak. Of course.
"The most significant news
"is the fact that
your first son, Sek,
"has gone through
the Pon farr.
"He mated and has
become a father.
"You are now the grandfather
of a healthy female
who they have named T'Meni,
after your mother."
You're a grandfather!
Isn't that wonderful?
Congratulations!
What should we call you now?
Grandpa? Gramps?
I think Commander
Tuvok will suffice.
Thank you, Mr. Neelix.
I'll read the rest to myself.
Just as long as you
read it right away.
No procrastinating.
Who knows what else
might be in that letter?
KIM:
Is that a letter
to you, Captain?
Yes. Seven just
downloaded it.
I'll be in my ready room.
Yes, ma'am.
Have you gotten a letter yet?
Don't expect one.
Do you remember Sveta?
Of course.
I got one from her.
Why would she
be writing you?
Chakotay, what is it?
Something terrible
has happened.
I read that letter for an hour
before I could accept it.
Now I have to tell
everyone else...
and I'm not sure
how to do it.
It's over, B'Elanna.
There are no more Maquis.
What are you saying?
There are thousands of us.
All wiped out.
It seems the Cardassians
have an ally...
a species from
the Gamma Quadrant
who supplied them
with ships and weapons.
Atara?
Roberto?
Everyone except us is dead?
Just about.
Sveta and a few lucky
ones are in prison.
No...
B'Elanna...
Don't! Don't try
to console me.
I don't want to be comforted.
Those were our friends...
good people willing to put
their lives on the line
for something they believed in
and now you're telling
me that they are gone...
that they are slaughtered.
Those are the risks we all took.
We knew where it could lead.
It's not right
and you know it.
I will make someone pay,
I swear I will.
( gasping )
If we ever get back.
Tom... I heard there are
at least 30 more letters
that have been downloaded.
Oh, yeah?
Neelix is supposed to
be on his way here now.
What do you suppose
this is, anyway?
What what is?
This mystery dish.
It tastes vaguely
like chicken,
but it has the consistency
of corn husks.
Is that all you
can think about--
what you're eating?
Well, I don't like guessing
at what I put in my stomach.
Tom... we're getting
letters from home.
Doesn't that mean
anything to you?
Not particularly.
I don't believe you.
You know, it's really
not that bad.
Here he comes.
Good news.
Seven has been able
to download some more letters.
This one is for
Susan Nicoletti.
Is she here?
Oh, yes.
Fitzpatrick.
Right here.
NICOLETTI:
Thank you.
Ah, Kyoto.
Golwat.
Thank you.
Ashmore.
Dorado.
I'm here.
There's not going
to be one for me.
He's not done yet.
Hang on.
And finally...
Parsons.
NEELIX:
I'm sorry if your name
hasn't come up,
but Seven is still working.
Neelix, I thought you
had over 30 letters.
30? Where did
you hear that?
That's what was going around.
Don't pay any attention
to rumors.
Right.
Aren't you going
to eat your lunch?
I'm not hungry.
You shouldn't get
your hopes up, Harry.
No hopes,
no disappointments.
I'm not you.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Captain, I'm beginning
to have trouble
accessing the datastream.
The longer it remains
lodged in the relay station,
the more it degrades.
If we could get near enough,
we could try to stabilize
the containment field,
but I can't risk taking
the ship in any closer.
A shuttle
could withstand
the gravimetric eddies
more easily than Voyager.
I'd like to try it.
I'd want Commander Tuvok
to go with you.
For what reason?
It isn't my custom
to send an away team of one.
As you wish.
( sighs )
Hi.
Hi. I thought Seven
was working in here.
She's gone with Tuvok
to shore up the station's
confinement field.
I've taken over for her.
Disappointed?
Of course not.
Would you stop that?
I've told you,
there's nothing between us.
I know there's
nothing between you.
It's purely
a one-way attraction.
Very funny.
Harry, you might as
well wear a big sign
that says, "I'm in love."
Everyone sees it.
Look, I'll admit
that for a while...
Well, she's a very
attractive woman,
but I've gotten over that.
Okay.
Fine. Believe
whatever you want.
If you didn't come
down here to see her,
why did you?
I wanted to know...
if I'd gotten a letter yet.
Sorry. I haven't
seen anything so far.
Do you think... there's going
to be one for everybody?
I'm sure
that Starfleet contacted
the families and friends
of everyone on this ship.
They know how important
that would be.
I hope so.
Harry... you'll get one.
Try to be patient.
Commander, am I correct
in assuming
that Vulcans are
incapable of lying?
We are capable
of telling lies.
However, I have never found it
prudent or necessary to do so.
You have never lied?
Only under orders from
a superior officer.
Then I must
ask you something.
Is it the Captain's custom
to send at least two people
on an away mission?
It's not only her custom,
it's recommended
Starfleet protocol.
I see.
Is there a purpose
to your question?
I am wondering if the Captain
still doesn't trust me--
if she feels
I require supervision.
I am not certain how
the Captain regards you,
but her decision to
have me accompany you
on this mission
shouldn't be taken
as evidence of any
particular attitude.
I believe we are close enough
to emit a polaron pulse.
Bring the main
deflector on line.
Ready.
The variance
in the containment field
is now at point-29.
That should prevent further
degradation of the signal.
Let me ask you
a question, Seven.
Is the Captain's opinion
important to you?
My understanding
of the hierarchy on Voyager
is that the Captain's opinion
is important to every
member of the crew.
( console beeping )
What's happened?
We've just been scanned
by a subnucleonic beam
of some kind.
The navigational sensors
have been disrupted.
We must get Voyager
to send out
a directional beacon
to guide us back.
Tuvok to Voyager.
Voyager,
please respond.
Commander, we've lost
other systems as well.
We have no communications,
no warp engines...
and no weapons.
I suspect this was
done intentionally
by the ship that's
approaching rapidly
off our port stern.
They're at 50,000 kilometers
and closing.
Our shields
are losing integrity.
I'll try to get at least one
phaser array back on line.
Commander, one more hit
and we'll be susceptible
to a hull breach.
That ship is larger than ours.
If we lure it
closer to the station,
it will be far more vulnerable
to the gravitational eddies
than we are.
A tractor beam.
We're being pulled
toward the ship.
I'll try to disrupt it.
Unsuccessful.
Launching a
distress beacon.
Torres to the Bridge.
JANEWAY:
Go ahead.
Captain, could Lieutenant Paris
come down here?
I think I've got something
he'd want to see.
He's on his way.
( door opens )
It's a letter for you.
It's coming through right now.
For me?
It's right here.
( clears throat )
Who's it from?
I can't tell yet.
Maybe it's from
the rehab colony
telling me
I've violated probation.
Why are you
acting like this?
I just want to know
who the letter's from, okay?
We should know in a minute.
I'll be on the Bridge.
What, you're not
going to wait?
I'm on duty.
Voyager is hanging in space.
There's not a lot to do
at the helm.
I just thought
that I should be at my post.
You may be able to fool
someone else with that ploy,
but you're talking
to me, Tom.
Just download the letter, okay?
A little more
has come in.
It's from Starfleet.
From... an Admiral Owen.
Do you know him?
Admiral Owen Paris.
That's my father.
That's wonderful.
Yeah, maybe.
( sighs )
I... I don't know
exactly why, but...
the more everybody gets excited
about these letters from home,
the more I don't want
any part of it.
Maybe because...
what I have on Voyager...
is so much better than anything
I ever had back there.
I just don't want
the reminder.
You're not the same person
you were four years ago.
What makes you think he is?
No. You don't know him.
At least give him a chance.
He's obviously reaching out.
When he forms an opinion
about something,
nothing can change his mind.
Fine.
Excuse me if I can't feel
terribly sorry for you.
I learned this morning that
a lot of my friends are dead
and I've gone
from being so angry
that I wanted to kill someone...
to crying for an hour.
And now I'm just trying to...
to accept it and move on.
B'Elanna... that's awful.
Oh, I am so sorry.
And here I am
going on about something
that doesn't even matter
anymore.
No, no. I'm sorry.
It obviously does.
You care what he thinks
about you.
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess I still do.
I'll let you know when
I get the whole letter.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Looks like Tuvok and Seven
pulled it off.
The containment field
has stabilized quite a bit.
B'Elanna says she's
downloading the letters
much more easily now.
That's good news.
They don't have the shuttle
on sensors yet,
but they should
be back soon.
I've learned a few
interesting things
about that relay station.
It's generating
as much energy
every minute as a typical
star puts out in a year.
What's amazing to me
is that someone
100,000 years ago
was harvesting
microsingularities.
If nobody shows up to protest,
I'd like to stay
here for a while--
try to find the answers
to some of these questions.
This is the kind of
archeological puzzle
that's always fascinated me.
Want a cup?
No, thanks.
You haven't mentioned
your letter.
Who was it from?
It was from Mark...
the man I was engaged to.
He told me about
the litter of puppies
my dog had-- how he
found homes for them,
how devastated he was
when Voyager was lost...
how he held out hopes
we were alive
longer than most people did...
until he realized that he
was clinging to a fantasy.
So he began living
his life again--
meeting people,
letting go of the past.
About four months ago,
he married a woman
who works with him.
He's very happy.
And how do you feel
about that?
Well, I knew he'd eventually
move on with his life...
but there was such
a finality to that letter.
Kim to the Captain.
Can you come to the Bridge?
What is it?
We picked up
an automated distress signal
from Tuvok's shuttle.
Sensors show there's
no one on board.
( groaning )
Seven.
Seven of Nine.
( groans )
Where are we?
I assume
we're on the alien ship.
This is most uncomfortable.
Have you seen anyone?
No.
If we can reach
one of those blades,
perhaps we can
cut through these bindings.
You were pathetic prey.
Easily taken.
The hunt was not satisfying.
I want information.
Why do you violate
our property?
I could snap your puny neck
with one twist.
Hardly worth taking.
Answer me. Why do you
use our modules?
We're trying to retrieve
important messages
from our home.
Return us to our ship
and we'll be on our way
without trespassing again.
I took you in a fair hunt.
I claim the relics
of the chase.
Are the others on your ship
able to put up more
of a fight than you?
You will find our Captain
a formidable opponent
and our ship heavily armed.
Good. Strong prey makes
for a better hunt.
Release us now
and you'll be safe.
Otherwise, we will destroy you.
( footsteps approaching )
Pitiful relics.
They are the first
of their kind.
I will be envied.
I've located their ship.
It's 4,000 ketrics
from the module.
We'll be there
within the hour.
Go to stalking mode.
Why do you hesitate?
The rest of the group
is on its way.
I wanted to claim
this prey for myself.
We may not be able
to take them alone.
We need the strength
of the others.
I won't share prey
with the others.
These two must be
the only relics! Prepare them!
KIM:
Captain.
It's tricky to scan
through the interference,
but I think I'm
detecting a ship.
What kind of ship?
Let me reconfigure
the sensor array.
It's Hirogen,
and Tuvok and Seven
are on it.
Hail them.
On screen.
I'm Captain Janeway
of the starship Voyager.
You have two
of my crew on board.
Disconnect your link
to our module
and leave this space.
Not without my people.
They are my relics.
I'm prepared to offer you
something for their safe return.
Surely we can come
to an agreement.
If the rest
of my group arrives,
you will be taken as well.
I'm giving you a chance to run.
We don't run.
Captain, I've got three
more ships on sensors
coming toward
us at high warp.
Don't be foolish.
Leave now and save yourselves.
Give me my people
and we'll do just that.
They're mine!
Then get ready
for a fight.
Red Alert.
Are they prepared?
Yes. But now is not
the time for it.
We should wait until
the others arrive
and take the ship.
I want to make
the first kill.
You will verify it.
If there is a battle,
we must join it.
The others can wage the battle.
Perhaps you are more interested
in collecting relics.
Perhaps your judgment
is clouded.
Don't question me again.
We do it now.
I suggest you think carefully
about your decision.
If you kill us, our Captain will
hunt you down and show no mercy.
I'm not concerned.
Lower the harness.
A long, coiled intestine--
an interesting trophy.
What possible use could you
make of my intestines?
Unusual relics are prized.
Yours will make me
envied by men
and pursued by women.
You are a crude species.
Only your size
makes you formidable.
Your insults are as pitiful
as your efforts to escape.
This one first.
I want the female
to witness
what will happen to her.
Their bone structure
makes cutting
through the back difficult.
This will take time.
Bridge to Torres.
Torres here, Captain.
How much longer?
I'm getting it out
piece by piece.
At least another half hour.
How are you coming?
That ship has some kind
of monotanium armor plating.
It's scattering
the targeting beam.
The other three ships are
within 6,000 kilometers.
PARIS:
Captain,
those ships
have massive weapons.
They've definitely
got us outgunned.
Harry, let me see those ships
in relation
to the relay station.
Yes, ma'am.
Maybe we can use that quantum
singularity to our advantage.
How?
If we can boost the effect
of the singularity--
increase the gravitational pull,
we might be able to stop them.
KIM:
The pull would
increase if we could weaken
the station's containment field.
An antithoron burst might do it.
If we're not careful,
we might be pulled in as well.
Don't worry.
We're going to be ready for it.
Harry, create a low-level
warp field around Voyager--
sublight energy level.
That should help counteract
the gravitational pull.
If the field is too strong,
we won't be able to beam
Tuvok and Seven aboard.
Then you'll have to find
the right balance,
won't you, Harry?
Yes, ma'am.
On my mark,
direct a level-8
antithoron burst
toward the station.
Have thrusters ready
for full reverse, Mr. Paris.
Understood.
I've established
a low-level warp field, Captain.
Antithoron system
is on line.
I'm ready with thrusters.
Do it.
It's working.
Try the transporter lock
again, Harry.
( alarm blaring )
Stabilize the ship!
I can't. The gravity well
is pulling us in!
( growls )
That vessel is weakening
the module's
containment field.
Ready weapons.
Signal the others to attack.
Torres to the Bridge.
Janeway here.
The antithoron burst
collapsed the signal.
I've gotten as much of the
message as I'm going to get.
Acknowledged.
Hail those ships.
Channel open.
This is Captain Janeway.
Agree to retreat, and we'll
restore the containment field.
Captain, they're firing!
Their weapons are destabilizing
the containment field!
This is Janeway.
Stop firing.
You're putting yourselves
in grave dan...
The field is going!
The singularity
is about to be exposed!
Captain, the ship
with Tuvok and Seven
is still being pulled in.
Get a tractor beam on it.
I have Tuvok
and Seven targeted,
but if we try to
transport them now,
the gravity well could
scatter their patterns.
The tractor beam is weakening.
We're going to lose them!
Harry, we have to risk it.
Activating the transporter.
Full reverse! Increase
power to the engines!
No response.
Do you have them?
Not yet. Their patterns
are distorting.
Narrow the annular
confinement beam.
Tractor beam's
almost gone, Captain.
We're losing
this tug-of-war.
Reroute all secondary power
to the tractor emitters.
The tractor beam collapsed.
That ship is headed
into the black hole.
KIM:
I'm realigning
the pattern buffer.
I've got one more shot at it.
I got them!
They're in Transporter Room 2.
I need more power!
We're being pulled in!
Transfer all available power
to the engines.
( console beeping )
It's not enough!
Shut down life support.
Structural integrity is failing.
The hull is starting
to buckle.
We're going in!
Open the antimatter injectors
to 120 percent.
Captain, that
could breach the core.
So will that black hole.
Now, just do it.
Yes, ma'am.
We're free.
Resume course.
I'll be in Astrometrics.
Captain, look at this.
The energy released
from the singularity
created a massive discharge
along the relay network.
It disabled every one
of the stations.
How much of the message
were you able to get?
I got most of the
encrypted Starfleet text
and a few more
personal letters.
How soon can we see
what Starfleet had to say?
Oh, it'll take
some time to decode.
Harry should
probably work on it.
Well, if you'll
excuse me,
I have a few letters
to deliver.
Neelix can do that.
No need.
Anyway, there's one
that I want to do personally.
Good news, Harry.
I got this
at the last minute.
It's from my folks.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, Tom.
I wasn't able to
download yours in time.
Just when I was getting eager
to read it.
You could assume
that he said he loves you...
and that he's proud of you.
I think I will.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Seven of Nine
and Commander Tuvok
suffered no serious
physical damage
after their encounter
on the alien ship.
I've been eager to hear
Tuvok's impressions
of the species
who took them hostage.
I learned very
little about them,
but I believe we should consider
them extremely dangerous.
They seem to lack
any moral center.
Do you know why
the relay network
was so important to them?
No. I assume they used it
for communications, as we did.
Well, they won't be
using it anymore.
They won't be pleased
about that, Captain.
I doubt we've seen
the last of them.
( door chimes )
Come in.
If you'll excuse me.
Commander.
Repair teams have inspected
the ship from stem to stern.
Except for some maintenance
that's needed on the warp coils,
everything seems fine.
I suppose so.
Want some coffee?
Thanks.
Cream and sugar?
Two sugars.
Oh... two sugars?
You know, you drink
too much of that stuff.
Really?
If I'm not mistaken,
that's your third
cup this morning.
Fourth. And on
a day like today,
it won't be my last.
Coffee: the finest organic
suspension ever devised.
It's gotten me
through the worst
of the last three years.
I beat the Borg with it.
Oh, I'm sure Voyager
will be fine.
But I'm worried that the crew
might be a different story.
I think they were
hoping mail call
would become a regular part
of their day.
Neelix is putting together
an impromptu party.
He thought it might
cheer them up.
Good idea.
When will it be?
As soon as he can
get people together.
Leave it to Neelix
to come up
with the right idea
at the right time.
How are you doing?
Me? I'm fine.
You'd say that
if you just had
your legs torn off
by a Trayken beast.
Look what you've been through
in the last few days.
We finally make
a connection with home
and then it's
ripped away from us.
We manage to make
another enemy
who's going to try
and hunt us down
and destroy us,
and on top of that...
It's all right.
You can say it.
On top of all that,
I got a "Dear John" letter.
It wasn't really a surprise.
I guess I didn't really
expect him to wait for me
considering the circumstances.
But it made me realize
that I was using him
as a safety net, you know--
as a way to avoid becoming
involved with someone else.
You don't have that
safety net anymore.
That's right.
But then again,
my life is far from uneventful
here in the Delta Quadrant.
It's not like I would
have had a chance
to pursue a relationship,
even if I had realized
I was alone.
You're hardly alone.
And to my way of thinking,
there's still plenty of time.
Plenty of time.
Neelix to the ready room.
The party's about to begin
and there are only
two people missing.
We're on our way.
( chuckling )