The prey's course
has become erratic.
I will intercept to kill.
No.
Maintain distance.
His ship is damaged.
He's injured.
Let him bleed.
This prey is resilient.
We will lose the moment.
The way a creature
behaves
when it is wounded
is the key to
its destruction.
Maintain distance.
Direct hit.
Our hull armor is stable.
His weapons must
be weakening.
The prey is heading
for an asteroid belt.
Vector 168.9.
We are losing him.
He hasn't come
here to hide.
He's come to make
a final stand.
Tracking.
He's holding position
above an asteroid
and he's left his ship.
Follow him.
The prey is scattering
our sensors.
Impressive.
He counters our pursuit
to the final moment.
Compensating.
No. Disengage sensors.
For what reason?
I want to take him
with my own eyes.
Follow.
I'll draw
his attack.
Prepare to target
his thoracic crest.
( rocks clattering )
( growls )
( snarling )
( snarling shrieks )
A flawless kill.
"Please remain still so that
I can treat your injuries.
"Thank you.
"I'm sorry. Did that hurt?
"I'll try to be more careful.
"Thanks for being
a patient patient.
Have a pleasant afternoon."
This is absurd.
Not at all.
Keep going.
You're doing fine.
This vernacular
is not applicable
to my duties on Voyager.
We can tailor the vocabulary
to your specific situations
a little later.
Right now, it's the
sentiment that counts.
I don't see the relevance.
I created these exercises
three years ago
to familiarize myself
with the social graces.
I found that if I repeated
them several times each day,
the words became
almost second nature.
Let's continue.
Exercise two:
"The workplace encounter."
Kes used to help me
with this one.
Now I'll be the nurse.
You be the doctor.
( sighs )
"Please hand me
the hypospray."
"Of course, doctor,
immediately."
"Thank you.
Looks at instrument."
No, no. Don't read that part--
only the dialogue.
"Excuse me, Nurse.
"This is the wrong
hypospray.
Would you mind finding
the correct one?"
"Not at all."
"Thank you."
"Did I mention you
look lovely today?"
"Oh, doctor,
you're so charming."
This lesson
is terminated.
I know it's awkward.
For me, it was
even painful,
but I think you'll find the
rewards well worth the effort.
Rewards.
The ability
to put others at ease...
make them feel more
comfortable around you.
You're a lot like me when
I was first activated.
If I'd had a mentor,
things would have gone
a lot more smoothly.
I'm willing to
share my wisdom,
but, if you're not
interested... fine.
I'll stick to your
physiological maintenance.
I will examine
your data.
Oh, good.
Pay special attention
to Exercise 17:
"Bridge banter
for beginners."
Have a pleasant day.
Hmm?
Verify.
Monotanium hull plating,
dicyclic warp signature--
the vessel is
definitely Hirogen.
They're moving to intercept.
Evasive maneuvers?
No. We need to settle
our differences here and now.
Hard about,
full impulse.
Red Alert.
They're in visual range.
On screen.
JANEWAY:
Hail them.
No response.
They're closing.
50,000 kilometers...
forty-five...
forty...
Maintain course, Mr. Paris.
Curious.
They are not
charging weapons.
PARIS:
They're slowing, sir.
CHAKOTAY:
Life signs?
TUVOK:
Only one.
And it's erratic.
They've stopped,
Captain.
Their engines just
went off-line.
This could be a trap.
Harry, run a long-range scan.
Are there any other
Hirogen ships out there?
None.
Take us within
transporter range.
You intend to board
their ship.
Yes.
The Hirogen vessel is
a potential threat.
We should destroy it.
Seven, what you
call a threat,
I call an opportunity...
to gain knowledge
about this species--
and in this case,
maybe even show some compassion.
There seems to be
a wounded pilot over there.
Our experience with
the Hirogen indicates
that compassion would
not be reciprocated.
And all of my experience says
we've got to take
that chance anyway.
JANEWAY:
Commander.
Tuvok, Paris,
you're with me.
Looks like there
was a fight.
Search for the life signs.
( squeaking )
Commander.
I'm reading bones,
muscle tissue...
from at least
nine different species.
It's all being broken down
by some sort of enzyme.
Perhaps this is their method
of denaturating their prey.
Either that... or it's dinner.
( sighs )
Looks like somebody
lost their helmet.
( yells )
Commander.
I'm not picking up
any weapon residuals.
I'd say he was
physically torn apart.
( tricorder beeping )
I'm picking up
the life signs.
This way.
( wheezing )
Massive internal bleeding.
Let's get him
to Sick Bay.
The data we downloaded
from the ship's computer
included
navigational records.
Can you give us a map
of this region?
This is the Hirogen vessel's
flight path
over the past five years.
They've certainly covered
a lot of space.
This ship alone has visited
over 90 star systems
in the last year.
I analyzed some of their logs.
From what I can tell,
this is a hunting species.
We saw the
skeletal remains
from dozens of alien races
displayed like trophies.
There was also evidence
they may be using some
of their victims for food.
The entire culture
seems to be based
on the hunt--
social rituals, art,
religious beliefs.
They're nomadic.
Their existence is driven
by the pursuit of prey.
And it's carried them
across huge distances.
There is no evidence
of a home planet.
Their ships travel alone
or in small groups.
On occasion,
several will join forces
in a multipronged attack.
Like wolves.
How's our "wolf" in Sick Bay?
TUVOK:
Still unconscious...
behind a level-5 force field.
You were right, Seven.
This species is a threat.
But despite the risk
of sending an away team,
we know a lot more about
who we're dealing with now.
You were correct, Captain.
It was worth the risk...
this time.
So, there's
one question remaining.
Who's hunting the hunters?
I was trying to remove
his body armor
to treat the
internal injuries,
when he suddenly
regained consciousness.
Needless to say,
he's not happy to be here.
Can you sedate him?
I've already tried.
His immune system
neutralizes everything.
I could synthesize
a more potent compound,
but that would take hours.
He could be dead by then.
His wounds are severe.
Your crewmate is dead...
and your ship has been damaged
beyond repair.
I brought you here
to treat your injuries.
What happened
to your ship?
Who attacked you?
The first time
I met your species,
it wasn't
on the best of terms,
but that doesn't mean
you and I
can't find a way
to change that.
Our prey.
You were on a hunt.
Yes.
A formidable alien.
We captured it two days ago,
but it broke free
of its restraints...
attacked us.
Release me.
I must continue the hunt.
Not without your ship
and not in this condition.
You'll die
without treatment.
Let us help you.
Doctor?
All right...
I'm going to enter
the force field now
and start with a few scans
of your midsection.
You should know I'm a hologram
and can't be bent,
spindled or mutilated
so don't bother trying.
Hmm.
Please lie down.
Or remain standing.
Captain, we've detected
six more Hirogen ships.
They're converging on us
from all directions.
The one in Sick Bay
may have sent a distress call
from his vessel.
How long do we have?
The nearest ship
is half a light-year away--
four hours at most.
Tom, analyze
their approach pattern.
Evade them as long as you can.
Yes, ma'am.
I want to buy the doctor enough
time to treat our hunter.
If I can gain his confidence,
he might call off his friends.
Good old-fashioned diplomacy
could get us out of this yet.
Don't count on it.
From what I found
in their database,
diplomacy isn't a part
of their lifestyle.
They don't see us as equals.
To them, we're simply game.
It's time
we convince them otherwise--
or like any other cornered
animal, we'll show our teeth.
TUVOK:
There's been
a hull rupture
on Deck 11, Section 3.
Damage is minor.
It appears
a plasma conduit overloaded.
Increase power to the structural
integrity field.
( rumble )
A bulkhead has collapsed
in Jefferies Tube 84.
Another overload?
KIM:
Negative.
The plasma network is stable.
This wasn't caused by any
power surge or system failure.
Harry, Tuvok, get to Deck 11
and check it out.
This was no overload.
Indeed.
Commander.
It's a dense mixture of DNA
and polyfluidic compounds.
Tuvok to Bridge.
JANEWAY:
Go ahead.
We may have
an intruder on board.
I'm analyzing what could be
a sample of its blood.
The readings are consistent
with Species 8472.
Intruder alert.
Bridge to Security.
Seal off Decks 10 through 12.
Internal sensors
aren't detecting any intruders.
The last time
we ran into this species,
it was impervious
to our scanners.
We'll have to track it visually.
How did it get
past our shields?
We'll worry about that later.
You have the Bridge, Commander.
I'll be on Deck 11.
I've erected a level-10 force
field around Engineering.
Good. Set up
secondary force fields
around every hatch,
Jefferies tube and conduit
leading into this room.
I want every one
of these consoles secured--
authorized
command codes only.
I'm going to lock down
the warp core.
Ensign, realign
the dilithium matrix
to a frequency of 3.69.
( hissing )
( snarling )
Report.
Four crew members are
wounded, two seriously.
Get them to Sick Bay.
Species 8472
accessed Engineering
through the antimatter
injector port.
Our phaser fire
was insufficient.
It attacked us,
then escaped
through Jefferies
Tube 17-Alpha.
Janeway to Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
The intruder
just left Engineering.
Seal off the area.
Understood.
Secure the warp core.
Yes, Captain.
Seven.
It would seem
that the Hirogen
underestimated
their latest prey.
You believe they were
hunting the creature.
Yes. When the Borg
were fighting Species 8472,
did they ever engage
in physical combat?
On many occasions.
Can you recall anything
that might help us here?
Each time they boarded
a Borg vessel,
they went directly to
the central power matrix
and disabled it.
The creature was just
in Engineering.
Didn't touch any
of our power systems.
It's obviously adjusted
its strategy.
Species 8472 is devious
and highly intelligent.
It will seek the most efficient
means of destroying us.
Let's get to Sick Bay.
DOCTOR:
She's going to be
just fine, Captain.
Is it alone?
Have you seen
any others like it?
Why?
Six months ago,
this species invaded our galaxy
with thousands of ships.
We were barely able
to fight them off.
Your prey could indicate
another invasion.
If it does,
we're all in trouble.
How many ships
have you seen?
Only one. Damaged.
We tracked it
across 50 light-years.
We thought that we had
killed the creature,
but this prey is
unlike any other.
It has many lives.
Lower the force field
and I will finish the hunt.
Your attempt to destroy
it will fail.
Species 8472 is highly
resistant to all technology.
All but one...
Borg nanoprobes.
"Nanoprobes"?
CHAKOTAY:
Microscopic
weapons that can
attack the species
on a cellular level.
We've tried it before
and it worked.
SEVEN:
I'll modify
the phaser rifles
to fire nanoprobe discharges.
I want you to incapacitate
the creature, not kill it.
Can you make
that modification?
Yes, but it would
require additional time.
We must stop it
as soon as possible.
She's right.
Not until we know
why it returned.
You will be exposing
this crew to unnecessary risk.
I disagree.
Captain...
You have your orders,
Seven.
Six of your vessels will be here
in under four hours.
I hope you'll let them know
that we saved your life
and we want to avoid any further
conflict with your people.
Let me resume the hunt,
and I will grant your request.
We have enough problems
on this ship as it is
without him running around.
I spent six months studying
this prey's behavior.
I know how to track him.
Let me continue
or I will have the others
destroy you.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Go ahead.
We're holding position
in Section 94,
but the creature has accessed
the environmental controls.
Deck 11 is losing life support.
Artificial gravity has also
been compromised.
Evacuate the deck.
Regroup on Deck 10.
Aye, Captain.
He's trying to
barricade himself.
He did the same thing to us.
You want to be
part of the hunt?
Now's your chance.
He'll be under
your supervision, Commander.
If he steps out of
line, shoot him.
My weapon.
CHAKOTAY:
Temperature gradient.
PARIS:
Affirmative.
Atmospheric recyclers.
Engaged.
Is your body armor
designed to handle
rapid pressure
fluctuations?
It can defeat most
hostile environments.
I once tracked
a silicon-based life-form
through the neutronium mantle
of a collapsed star.
I once tracked a mouse
through Jefferies Tube 32.
Chakotay to Tuvok.
We're ready to go.
As are we.
Proceed to Deck 11.
Keep your com links open.
Understood. Activate
the nanoprobe charges.
Level five should be sufficient
to stun the creature.
Depressurizing hatch.
Magnetize.
Maintain your position.
He's here.
I said maintain
your position.
This is my hunt.
I'm at point.
My knowledge of this prey
is superior to yours.
But you're on
unfamiliar terrain.
I know this ship.
You don't.
The prey will likely attack
the man at point.
You would not survive.
I'll take that chance.
Now, fall back.
No problem.
I'll take up the rear.
You missed.
Since Species 8472
invaded the ship,
you've become
increasingly agitated.
They were the only species
to offer true resistance
to the Borg.
They destroyed
millions of drones,
hundreds of our worlds.
I have reason to be agitated.
PARIS:
What is it?
It's blood.
The prey is wounded.
This corridor ends
about 20 meters ahead.
The only thing down there
is Deflector Control.
It's got nowhere to run.
He is not planning to run.
He is waiting.
He'll attempt to slip around us,
attack from behind.
Chakotay to Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
We've cornered
the intruder in Section 59.
On our way.
( moaning snarl )
It's hurt.
This prey is resilient.
He will strike
with his dying breath.
We must kill him now.
That may not
be necessary.
Hold your fire.
I said lower
your weapon!
( grunts )
( yells )
( squealing cries )
( gasps )
( weak snarling )
Mr. Neelix, I must ask you
to exchange your spatula
for a phaser rifle.
Sir?
We have
two intruders onboard
and six Hirogen vessels
on the way.
I need additional
security personnel.
Right away, sir.
What's my assignment?
Join the security detail
on Deck 10, Section 12.
You'll receive
further instructions there.
I'll expect tactical updates
every 20 min...
( gasping )
Lieutenant?
Are you all right?
You have your orders.
Report.
The Hirogen's
back in Sick Bay
within a force field.
And Species 8472?
We've established
a security perimeter.
Basically, we've turned this
entire section into a brig.
As an added precaution,
have B'Elanna start working
on a way
to lock onto the creature,
in case we have to beam it
off the ship.
You mentioned it was injured.
In what way?
I wish I could tell
you for certain.
Its body is generating
some sort bioelectric field
making it impossible
to scan,
so I could only make
a visual diagnosis.
It's conscious
but immobile.
Its epidermis displays
any number of injuries--
punctures, energy burns--
and its demeanor is that
of a wounded animal.
The Hirogen said they'd been
chasing it for several months.
Is there anything
you can do?
I don't know enough
about its physiology
to treat
the surface wounds,
let alone
any internal damage.
Frankly, I'm at a loss.
Captain, just
before we cornered it,
Species 8472 accessed deflector
control from this panel.
I've analyzed
the transmission protocols.
It was attempting to open
a singularity into its realm,
but it failed.
It was trying
to get home.
That's what it looks like.
( weak snarling moan )
Tuvok?
The creature
initiated telepathic
contact with me.
What's it saying?
Its ship was damaged during
the conflict with the Borg.
When the other members
of its species retreated
into fluidic space...
it was left behind.
It has been trapped in the
Delta Quadrant ever since...
alone...
pursued
by Hirogen hunting parties.
It has no desire
for further conflict.
It only wants to return
to its domain.
It is dying,
Captain.
You have nothing
to be afraid of.
We're going to help you
get back to your realm.
Does it
understand?
It does.
It will
take time
to open a singularity,
and we have no way
of treating your injuries,
but if there's anything
you can tell us about your...
( snarling groans )
It has lost
consciousness.
Our telepathic link
has been severed.
Where is my prey?
Lying at the end
of a corridor
on Deck 11...
nearly dead thanks to you.
Take me to it.
No.
Take me to it!
In less than three hours,
your ships will arrive.
By that time, Species 8472
will no longer be on Voyager.
What do you mean?
I'm sending it back
where it came from.
Surrender the creature to me
and you will not be harmed.
This isn't a hunt;
it's a slaughter.
And I'm calling it off
right now.
We will not be denied our prey.
Give us the creature....
or your crew
will take its place.
Tuvok?
Have Seven of Nine
report to my ready room.
You intend to ask her
to open a rift
into 8472's realm.
She's the only one
on board who knows how.
Given her feelings
toward the species,
she may not want
to cooperate.
We'll see.
You wish to see me,
Captain?
I've made a decision
about Species 8472.
I'm going to return it
to fluidic space.
In order to do that, I need you
to open a quantum singularity.
I don't believe that is
a prudent course of action.
I realize it may be
difficult for you to help
save this creature's life,
but part of becoming human
is learning to have compassion
for those who are suffering,
even when they're
your bitter enemies.
Why?
I remember
when I was a Lieutenant.
It was during
a Cardassian border conflict.
My away team was cut off
while we were defending
a Federation outpost.
We'd been exchanging
phaser fire
with a group of Cardassians
for about three days--
a stalemate.
One night, during
a break in the fighting...
we could hear
this low moaning sound
coming from somewhere
in the brush.
We knew that none of
our people were out there,
so it had to be
a wounded Cardassian.
Well, you have to understand--
we'd been killing each other
for weeks on this planet.
It was brutal.
But our commanding officer
decided...
that we couldn't just sit there
and listen
to that poor man suffer.
So he ordered me
and an Ensign...
to crawl out there
and bring that Cardassian
back to our camp.
I thought he was crazy.
He was risking our lives
for someone
who would have shot us
without hesitation.
But we did it...
and the Cardassian lived.
Three days later,
we secured the outpost.
It was a major victory.
We were all decorated
by Starfleet Command,
but in retrospect...
the thing I'm most proud of
was the night we saved
that man's life.
Explain.
A single act of compassion
can put you in touch
with your own humanity.
You are trying to justify
your present decision.
No.
I'm trying to help you see
this as an opportunity to grow.
I know you don't want
to do it, Seven,
but I'm telling you
as your Captain
and as your friend,
you won't regret it.
No.
Your decision is
tactically unsound.
We will be surrounded
by Hirogen ships
in approximately two hours.
If we do not surrender
the creature,
they will destroy us.
A lesson in compassion
will do me little good
if I am dead.
It is wrong to sacrifice
another being
to save our own lives.
I have observed that
you have been willing
to sacrifice your own life
to save the lives of your crew.
Yes, but that's different.
That was my choice.
This creature
does not have a choice.
It invaded our ship,
put our lives at risk
to save its own.
In my view, it has already
forfeited its freedom.
I'm giving you an order.
Report to Deflector Control
and begin working
on creating a singularity.
I will not comply.
I have agreed
to remain on Voyager.
I have agreed to function
as a member of your crew,
but I will not be a willing
participant
in my own destruction
or the destruction of this ship.
Objection noted.
We'll do this without you.
You will fail.
And you have just
crossed the line.
End of debate.
Report to the cargo bay
and remain there
until this is over.
Is that understood?
Shields down to 84 percent.
Return fire.
Three more ships are closing
from port and starboard.
All escape trajectories
have been cut off.
Our weapons are having little
effect on their hull plating.
I'm scanning for weaknesses
in the molecular structure.
Shields at 79 percent.
TUVOK:
They are hailing us.
Better late than never.
Open a channel.
You've taken our prey
and one of our hunters.
Surrender them.
Call off your attack
and we'll return your crewman.
As for your prey,
it's under our protection now.
It belongs to us.
It belongs to no one.
Now, order your ships
to withdraw
and this can end peacefully.
All vessels are firing.
Any luck finding a
crack in their armor?
Not yet.
Doctor to Bridge.
Species 8472
appears to be regenerating.
I'm no exobiologist,
but I'd say this fellow
is becoming highly agitated.
It could be sensing
the Hirogen attack.
Doctor, can you sedate it?
I believe so,
but I'll need another dose
of Borg nanoprobes.
Stand by.
Bridge to Seven of Nine.
Yes.
Report to Deck 11 immediately
with a supply of nanoprobes.
Understood.
B'Elanna, how's it going
down there?
Transporters are ready.
I can establish a lock
on the creature at any time,
but I still haven't duplicated
the deflector protocols
to open a singularity.
How long?
I need another hour...
maybe two.
Captain, we can outmaneuver
the Hirogen ships
for a few more minutes,
but beyond that...
Direct hit
to the EPS manifold!
Main power just went down!
Force fields on all decks
are off-line.
Switch to auxiliary power.
Done. Force fields
have been restored,
but I don't know
how long they'll hold.
Bridge to doctor.
Report.
It's all right, Captain.
The creature is contained.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Security respond.
Security,
dispatch teams to Deck 5.
The Hirogen may be loose.
Direct hit
to our port nacelle.
Now, they've taken out
our starboard nacelle.
They've crippled us.
Tuvok, divert warp power
to the phaser banks.
Maybe that'll help us
penetrate their
hull plating.
The nanoprobes?
Armed and ready.
Not a moment too soon.
( groaning )
Give me the prey.
Lower your weapon
or I will destroy you.
I don't think you will.
You want me to destroy
this creature.
I saw it on your face
earlier in the medical bay.
It's a look I've seen
a thousand times.
Stand aside.
( snarling fiercely )
What are you doing?
Captain, someone's accessing
the transporter system
from Deck 5.
Lock them out.
I can't.
They're overriding
my commands...
with Borg encryption codes.
JANEWAY:
Report, Mr. Kim.
8472 and the Hirogen...
they've been beamed to one
of the attacking ships.
All six vessels are moving away
at high warp.
Tom, can we pursue?
I'm sorry, Captain.
Warp engines
are still off-line.
Resume our
previous course.
Full impulse.
Seven of Nine?
Seven of Nine.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51652.3.
It's been 12 hours
and our sensors show no sign
of any Hirogen vessels,
but their people are scattered
throughout this region
and something tells me
that the "hunt" for
Voyager is far from over.
Captain.
Step down, please.
Seven, you disobeyed
my direct orders
and as a result,
you condemned a sentient
being to its death.
By doing so, I also diverted
the Hirogen attack,
an attack which
would have destroyed us.
Maybe not.
In any case, the decision
wasn't yours to make.
The creature broke the force
field. I had no choice.
I didn't come here to
debate your decision.
I came here to inform you
of the consequences.
When you first
came to Voyager,
I decided to grant you
the same liberties
and freedoms of any crew member
because I wanted you to
be a part of this family.
And I've been willing
to accommodate your...
unique way of doing things--
even when you rubbed
somebody the wrong way
or violated protocol.
But this time,
I can't accommodate you.
From this point forward,
you will no longer have access
to any primary systems
on this ship--
not without my
direct authorization.
If you attempt
to circumvent me,
I'll throw you in the brig.
I still need your expertise
in the Astrometrics
Lab if you're willing.
If not, you can spend your
time here in the cargo bay.
Is that understood?
Yes.
It is puzzling.
What's that?
You made me into an individual.
You encouraged me
to stop thinking
like a member of the collective,
to cultivate my independence
and my humanity.
But when I try to assert that
independence, I am punished.
Individuality has its limits...
especially on a starship where
there's a command structure.
I believe
that you are punishing me
because I do not think
the way that you do,
because I am not becoming
more like you.
You claim to respect
my individuality,
but in fact,
you are frightened by it.
As you were.