( dramatic theme playing )
Direct hit.
The target buoy
is solid monotanium,
ten meters thick,
shielded by a chromoelectric
force field.
Impressive.
I'm glad
you agree.
It's not wise to
travel this region
without adequate
defenses.
I've seen
scuttled ships
with more firepower
than Voyager.
I'm sure you have.
Imagine what you'll be capable
of once the isokinetic cannon
is integrated into
your defensive systems.
One projectile
can penetrate the shields
of any heavily armored
vessel.
Hostile species will
know to avoid Voyager
by reputation alone.
You've made your point,
Mr. Kovin.
I want the cannon.
And I'm prepared
to give you...
astrometric charts
spanning 12 sectors.
You'll find them
unusually precise.
Even the most sophisticated
charts become obsolete.
One random anomaly, and
they're no longer accurate.
However...
I could be persuaded
if you were to include
the mapping technology
that created them.
Sorry.
Our astrometric sensors
were designed specifically
for this ship.
They'd be of no use
to you.
What I can offer you
is a generous supply of
isolinear processing chips.
We'll even show you
how to integrate them
into your existing
sensor technology.
How generous a supply?
One hundred chips.
One hundred fifty.
115.
125--
Done. Escort our guest
to engineering.
You'll be
supervising
the installation
of the cannon?
Of course...
for a modest fee.
Five additional chips.
No more.
It's good to see
the art of negotiation
isn't lost on you,
captain.
( door closes )
That guy is worse
than a Ferengi.
Assign Seven of Nine
to work on this.
She's got a knack for adapting
alien technology.
Should I give her
complete access
to the engineering
control systems?
I'm ready to give her
some latitude.
She's been behaving herself
lately.
( door opens )
( beeping )
What are
you working on?
I'm trying to
decode the message
Starfleet Command sent us
several weeks ago.
Any progress?
None.
I'm working on a new
decryption algorithm.
I'd like you to set it
aside for a while.
I have another
assignment for you.
( beeping )
What is it?
The Captain wants you
to help Kovin
integrate
the new weapon system.
I'd rather not.
I find him inefficient.
Maybe so, but you seem
to work well with him.
You've been asking
for more responsibilities.
I thought you'd be pleased.
The captain gives me
greater liberty
only when she needs
my expertise.
You violated her trust,
and if you want it back,
you're gonna have to earn it,
one step at a time.
( dramatic theme playing )
I will report to engineering.
You'll need to install
isolinear buffer circuits
here and here.
The main
power relay
should be protected
by a containment field.
Unnecessary.
All the buffer circuits
would have to fail
simultaneously
for there to be
any danger.
We prefer to play it safe.
I'll check the inventory logs
to see if we have
a field generator
available.
( beeping )
What are you doing?
I'm reconfiguring
the tactical control systems.
The isokinetic circuits
requires
a specialized protocol.
Let me
take care of it.
That won't be
necessary.
( beeping continues )
No. No!
The subroutines need
to be arranged
in cascading sequence!
Let me show you.
( grunts )
( dramatic theme continues )
TORRES:
Seven, stop.
( sighing )
( triumphant theme playing )
DOCTOR:
There's a hairline fracture
of the premaxilla bone.
( Kovin gasping )
Do you see this, Captain?
She shattered it.
It's easily repaired.
Do you have any idea why
Seven attacked you?
It was unprovoked.
She came at me like an animal.
Well, I wouldn't put it
like that.
I was at another console
about 10 meters away.
I heard Kovin raise his voice,
and when I looked around,
I saw that he was holding
her arm.
I barely touched her!
A gentle gesture
to move her out of my way,
so I could get to
the console.
Then she turned on me,
attacked me.
What did you say
to her?
I told her
how to reconfigure
the tactical control
systems properly.
Is that all?
That's all.
And that's when
she knocked him down.
Ashmore and I
had to hold her back.
She would have killed me.
That woman is dangerous.
It's a miracle you survived.
Now hold still,
or this won't heal properly.
Why are you questioning me
on this?
You should be disciplining
your crew member.
Believe me,
I'll deal with it.
Please accept
my sincere apology.
Now,
if you'll excuse me.
Good as new.
( groaning )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Here we are again.
Oh, I'm tired of having
this conversation.
You know what
I'm going to say.
I know how
you're going to respond,
so it seems pointless
to say anything.
Shall I consider my privileges
restricted
and confine myself
to the cargo bay?
I think we've
established that
traditional
disciplinary actions
don't work with you.
The question is,
what will?
Are you asking for
my opinion?
I suppose I am...
Because frankly,
I'm running out of options.
Throwing you in the brig
isn't gonna solve anything.
Neither is slapping you
on the wrist.
And it's not as though
I don't understand
your feelings about Kovin.
There have been a few times
when I'd have liked
to pop him in the nose
myself,
but you have to start learning
the difference
between having an impulse
and acting on it.
Does that make
any sense to you?
I believe so.
I will give it more thought.
( sighs )
Well, that's a start.
I hear there was some
excitement this morning.
When I started helping you
improve your social skills,
I'm fairly certain I didn't
include a boxing lesson.
You weren't hurt,
were you?
No.
Still a bit tense?
Perhaps.
I understand
the burden you carry...
constantly being obligated
to deal with those
who fall short of
excellence.
I often find
my own patience
being tested by someone
like Mr. Kovin.
Of course, I generally respond
with a devastating quip
rather than a left hook.
( beeping )
We must both accept
the fact that
very few life-forms will
ever meet our high standards.
So when you
get irritated,
just try to be tolerant,
and remember...they can't help
being what they are.
Hm...I'm reading some
increased engramatic activity
and your adrenaline levels
are slightly elevated.
What does that indicate?
It's consistent with a state
of heightened tension.
Lie down and
I'll run some scans.
In a typical human,
I would consider this
a mood swing,
but with your unique physiology,
I'd like to rule out
the possibility of
a chemical imbalance.
( beeping )
( gasps )
Have you been experiencing
any other symptoms...
headaches,
disorientation?
No.
( ominous theme playing )
( heavy breathing )
( beeping )
Physiological scans
seem normal.
I'm going to check
your Borg implants now.
( gasps )
Seven, what's wrong?
Let me out.
I will. Stay calm.
( gasping )
No more procedures.
All right.
Stay away!
You mustn't do this.
Do what?
Seven,
what are you so afraid of?
I don't know.
She experienced an episode
of acute anxiety
with all the trimmings--
Intense apprehension,
shortness of breath,
dizziness.
I finally managed
to sedate her.
Could this have been caused
by her cortical implants?
I don't think so.
I think the problem has to do
with memory suppression.
I've detected
a high concentration
of biogenic amines
in Seven's hippocampus,
a substance
I haven't noticed before.
It's blocking several portions
of her memory center.
Do you know
where it came from?
No, but it seems to be
dissipating.
Seven's unusual
behavior may be the result
of the blocked memories
beginning to surface,
memories which she can't
identify yet.
Can you treat her?
Treatment would
involve integrating
the repressed memories
into Seven's consciousness.
I may be able to use
a standard therapeutic
regression technique.
I wasn't aware
that you were programmed
with psychotherapeutic
capabilities.
I wasn't, but in the absence
of a ship's counselor,
I've been developing
a psychiatric subroutine
to add to my program.
I'll be even more
valuable to you
than I am now.
Keep me informed,
doctor.
Hm.
DOCTOR:
A Jungian therapist
would attempt to retrieve
unconscious memories
by exploring synchronicities
in recent events.
On the other hand,
Amanin of Betazed would argue
that a combination of
sensory isolation
and focused breathing techniques
would be more effective.
I've integrated
the finer points of both
to create my own approach
to memory reconstruction.
What does this approach
involve?
First,
putting you at ease
by performing the treatment
here in your own environment.
Once the
cortical probes
have reinforced
the neural pathways,
I'll use a directed
imagery technique
to guide you through
the regression.
You may proceed.
Please,
close your eyes.
Clear your mind.
Try not to think
or to analyze.
My mind
is now clear.
Seven, this isn't
an exercise in efficiency.
Close your eyes.
Breathe deeply.
Now concentrate on
the sound of my voice.
Let go of the present.
Leave the cargo bay behind.
Allow yourself...
to drift.
( dramatic theme playing )
Describe the first image
that enters your mind.
A medical tricorder.
Duratanium casing,
7.6 centimeters
by 9.8 centimeters
by 3.2 centimeters.
Alpha-numeric
display--
That's enough.
So...
You're in Sickbay.
How does the tricorder
make you feel?
SEVEN:
It disturbs me.
DOCTOR:
Why does it
disturb you?
I'm afraid
it will hurt me.
Is there anything
else there
that causes you
to anticipate pain?
The diagnostic bed.
SEVEN:
It's closing around me.
DOCTOR:
You feel restrained,
confined.
SEVEN:
Yes. I'm uneasy.
DOCTOR:
About what?
It's Kovin.
DOCTOR:
What is he doing?
SEVEN:
He's restraining me.
I want to get away from him,
but I can't.
SEVEN:
Kovin's using some kind
of instrument on me.
( gasps )
Seven?
I didn't recall this before.
Recall what?
Kovin, he...
He performed
a surgical procedure on me.
He...
extracted Borg technology
from my body.
He violated me.
DOCTOR:
We're making progress.
Now, tell me.
This surgical procedure...
When did it happen?
I don't know.
The details are vague.
There are only images.
And you're sure
it was Kovin?
Did you see Kovin?
Yes.
You said
he was restraining you,
using an instrument
of some sort.
He was.
Were you on Voyager
when this happened?
No.
It must have been
when we were
testing the weapons
on the surface.
Then concentrate on
that away mission.
Focus on the first image
that enters your mind.
Describe it for me.
A large, granitic stone...
approximately
one-half meter high.
Now, allow that memory
to develop beyond the image.
Integrate it into
your consciousness.
Let the memory
take shape.
( dramatic theme playing )
SEVEN:
I'm at the weapons range.
Kovin had taken us there
to evaluate
various handheld firearms
he wished to offer
in trade.
He attempted to impress us
with a demonstration
of the weapons'
destructive capabilities.
My role was to provide
a more objective analysis.
Terawatt powered
particle-beam rifle.
Four microsecond
recharge cycle.
Ten kilometer range.
Definitely not standard
Starfleet issue.
What do you think?
72 percent fragmentation,
28 percent vaporization.
Crude, but efficient.
It's not as accurate
as our compression rifles,
but it's a lot easier
to handle.
I wouldn't mind
carrying one of these
the next time we run
into the Hirogen.
SEVEN:
The targeting mechanism
could be augmented
with a thermal
guidance sensor.
That would increase
accuracy by 24 percent.
I can do that now.
Care to join me?
You can make sure
that the adjustments
are performed
to your specifications.
PARIS:
If you don't mind,
I'd like to
test some of
the other firearms.
Go right ahead.
This way.
SEVEN:
Kovin took me
to a small laboratory.
DOCTOR:
Describe it.
SEVEN:
It was poorly illuminated.
I saw various instruments,
technology unfamiliar to me.
I assumed this was where he
developed new weapon designs.
( beeping )
This weapon
is thoron-based.
Most of these handheld
disruptors are.
Thoron can be unstable
in weapons.
Not if you polarize
the emitter matrix.
That compensates
for any instabilities.
Watch.
What are you doing?
He turned
the weapon on me.
He fired?
Yes,
I remember it now.
What happened next?
I'm not sure.
Concentrate.
See the laboratory
in your mind.
There was a light
in my eyes.
DOCTOR:
Was Kovin still
in the room with you?
SEVEN: Yes.
Restrain her. Quickly.
SEVEN:
And another Entharan
was assisting him.
This is
Borg technology.
KOVIN:
That's what I've been
telling you.
Let me go.
They bound me
to an examination table.
What did they do to you?
Did they scan you?
The bio-ablation pump
is engaged and pressurized.
( groaning, panting)
The growth medium
is activating the implants.
The nanoprobes are
multiplying.
( gasping )
They put a device
near my head.
SEVEN:
They removed
my ocular implant.
And...
some of the implants in my arm
were activated.
Which ones?
Can you be more specific?
KOVIN:
Use the maximum setting
of the metagenic pulse
to stimulate
the implants.
WOMAN:
The assimilation tubules
are ready.
Prepare to harvest
the nanoprobes.
SEVEN:
They extracted nanoprobes
through my
assimilation tubules.
I was powerless,
unable to stop them.
DOCTOR:
You couldn't be expected to.
You were restrained.
Then what happened?
SEVEN:
They took the nanoprobes
to another subject,
also restrained,
and they...
...they assimilated him.
Well done.
The next thing I remember,
I was back in Kovin's lab.
He claimed the particle-beam
rifle overloaded,
that it burned my hand,
but it was a lie.
They had attacked me.
I'm sorry.
I should have been more careful.
Do you have
a dermal regenerator?
Of course.
I'll inform the captain.
( door opens, closes )
There's no doubt
that Seven was the victim
of a brutal assault.
How is she?
As well as can
be expected.
She's regenerating
in her alcove.
I predict her emotional recovery
will take some time.
I certainly hope you intend
to hold Kovin responsible
for what he's done.
First, I want to know
how much of her story
we can corroborate.
Tom, you were with her
on the planet.
How long was she alone
with Kovin?
At least two hours.
When she came back, did she say
anything about what happened?
Only that they'd finished
their work on the rifle.
She seemed fine.
Clearly, Mr. Kovin used
some artificial means
to suppress her memory
of the event.
That would explain the unusual
engramatic activity
I found
in her neurological scans.
Did you find any other
physical evidence
of the medical procedures
she described?
No.
I suspect Mr. Kovin
used Seven's own nanoprobes
to repair
any cellular damage.
She distinctly remembers
Kovin extracting them.
You seen to be accepting Seven's
recovered memories as fact.
Are you suggesting
otherwise?
Historically, recovered memories
have often proven unreliable.
Yes, in cases where
a traumatic experience
has been repressed
for years.
But we're dealing with
a very recent memory here
that was blocked by
artificial means.
When I removed
that mechanism,
Seven remembered
everything that happened.
Human memory
is rarely perfect.
What are you saying,
Tuvok?
That Seven
is making this up?
No,
but we must remember
that she's experienced
hallucinatory images before.
That was in direct response
to a signal from the ship
where she was assimilated.
She's not having
hallucinations now.
She's remembering
what happened to her.
I've confirmed this
by analyzing the specific
engramatic activity
in her hippocampus. We're not
talking about conjecture.
We're talking about science.
Let's not
get bogged down.
Seven has made
serious accusations,
and I won't
dismiss them.
If Kovin assaulted her
and took a sample
of her Borg technology,
we can't stand by
and do nothing.
In the wrong hands,
a single nanoprobe
could lead to disaster.
Doctor, I want you
to keep searching
for any physical evidence
to back up Seven's claim.
I will talk to Kovin.
Dismissed.
( door opens, closes )
This is offensive
and absurd!
She's obviously
lying.
Why would she
do that?
Maybe you can answer that.
She's your crew member.
First,
she attacks me,
then she invents
these ridiculous stories,
and you try
to place the blame on me.
Is this some kind
of negotiating tactic?
I have
no hidden agenda.
I'm simply trying
to clarify what happened.
I told you already.
We went to my laboratory
to adjust the guidance system
on the particle-beam rifle.
And that took two hours?
She insisted on
absolute precision.
We've confirmed
that Seven was exposed
to an intense
thoron discharge.
She was. After the rifle's
power cell overloaded.
We reported
the accident immediately.
She now remembers that you fired
the weapon at her deliberately.
That's preposterous.
The doctor tells me
the blast could have been enough
to render her unconscious.
But it didn't.
We were both startled
for a moment,
and after I apologized
for the accident,
she asked if I had
a dermal regenerator,
which I did,
and I used it on her arm,
the one with
the mechanical implants.
Which you recognized
as Borg.
I was aware
she'd been a Borg.
She told me herself.
Did you ever express curiosity
in that technology,
or try to examine it
more closely?
No.
You never considered
the potential value
it might have
as a weapon?
Is that what you think
I've done?
You may not realize
how dangerous
Borg technology can be.
If you've taken even
a single nanoprobe,
I need to know
about it right now.
I haven't taken anything.
I'd like to examine
your laboratory
to be absolutely sure.
No.
This has already gone
too far.
Then I'll have to contact
the authorities.
Maybe they'll be
more helpful.
Are you willing to risk
our trade agreement
all on the basis of
one crew member's delusions?
Yes.
Now...
are you going to cooperate
with our investigation?
I don't seem to have
much choice.
You stated that the rifle's
power cell overloaded
as a result of a faulty
oscillator adjustment.
That's right.
Can you describe in more detail
how that occurred?
I was showing her how to
polarize the emitter matrix.
I must have tuned the
induction frequency too high.
Were you unfamiliar
with that procedure?
No.
I have done it 100 times.
It was
a careless mistake.
How many times do I need
to apologize?
I am not seeking
a statement of remorse.
Then what do you want?
Are you trying to catch me
in a lie?
Trick me into confessing?
You can't, because there's
nothing for me to confess!
I haven't done
anything wrong!
One of our crew members
claims that you have.
Your crew member,
Seven of Nine...
she's very fortunate.
How so?
She has an entire crew
leaping to her defense.
I have no one.
The Entharan representative
will be here shortly.
You mean the Magistrate?
He won't help me.
He's more interested in
protecting diplomatic relations
with people like you.
Surely,
he'll want to know the truth.
That's all we're seeking.
You don't
understand.
On my world, we depend on trade
with alien species.
There are strict protocols
about those relationships.
Even being accused of
violating them
is a serious offense.
You will have the opportunity
to refute any charges.
It won't matter.
Once they're made,
the damage is done.
I won't be trusted
any longer.
I'll be ruined.
Please...
I never hurt
your crew member.
Don't do this.
I'm afraid
I have no choice.
But I assure you,
our investigation
will be conducted
in a fair and
impartial manner.
You strike me as a man
of your word.
If you tell me
I won't be prejudged,
then I believe you.
( dramatic theme playing )
How are you feeling?
I am undamaged.
But how do you feel?
Seven, your physical
scars have healed,
but the psychological effects
are still there.
You'll have to deal
with them.
For what purpose?
In order to heal.
Kovin attacked you...
violated your rights
as an individual.
It's important that you
recognize that
so you can understand
any hostility or resentment
you might be feeling.
Resentment
is a human trait.
It has no structure,
no function.
I want no part of it.
You're going to have
to begin accepting
the fact that your
human feelings exist,
and that suppressing them
can damage you.
If I am not aware of
these feelings,
how can I
express them?
Let me ask you this.
What would have happened
if Kovin had tried to
take Borg technology
directly from
the Collective?
He would have been
assimilated.
Precisely.
Which is why he chose you.
He could get
what he wanted
without running
any risks.
It was my individuality
which made me vulnerable.
Exactly.
He violated
that individuality.
What he did is an affront
to everything you are.
Borg and human.
It was the act of a coward.
Yes!
Someone who was
willing to use you
in the cruelest way
so that he could
create new weapons
and sell them.
I believe I'm beginning
to experience anger.
Anger toward Kovin.
Good. That's a perfectly
healthy, normal response.
And when Kovin gets
what he deserves,
you're going to feel
much better.
( dramatic theme playing )
KOVIN:
Right this way, Magistrate.
My laboratory.
( dramatic theme continues
playing )
There are no
examination tables.
I told you.
Just workbenches.
Is this
the entire facility?
Yes.
We should scan
for signs
that the room may have been
altered recently.
During her regression,
Seven described instruments
similar to these.
Of course she did.
She was here.
DOCTOR:
She said a device
like this was used to remove
her optic implant.
That's a micro-caliper.
I used it
to remove the casings
over the guidance system
on the particle-beam rifle.
And isn't this
an electrodynamic probe?
Yes.
Hm.
It's equipped with
a monofilament stimulator.
Could it be used to manipulate
the neurotransmitter levels
in a human brain?
Not as it is.
But with the proper
modifications?
With the proper
modifications,
I could reconfigure
your combadge
to manipulate
neurotransmitters.
What's your point?
I believe
you've just made it.
( tricorder beeping )
There's cellular residue
on many of these instruments.
It matches
Seven's genome.
With your permission,
sir,
I'd like to take these tools
back to Voyager
where I can run
more conclusive scans.
Take whatever you need.
TUVOK:
Doctor, there are a number
of Borg nanoprobes
on the surface of
this table.
I'll just
collect a sample.
( beeping )
Hm...
That's where
her arm was hit
when the rifle
overloaded.
The dispersal pattern
is consistent
with a
dermal rupture.
These nanoprobes were
recently regenerated.
If this were nothing more
than cellular residue
from Seven's injury,
the nanoprobes
would be dormant.
But these have been activated
in a very specific pattern.
I've seen enough.
Kovin,
there is sufficient
evidence here
to detain you, pending
official proceedings.
No!
Please...
Stay where you are!
Kovin,
don't...
KOVIN:
I trusted you.
You said it would be
an impartial investigation,
but you're all determined
to find what you want to find.
Well, I'm not gonna
let this happen.
( combadge beeps )
Tuvok to Voyager.
JANEWAY:
Janeway here.
Mr. Kovin has transported
out of the laboratory.
TUVOK:
Can you track
his present position?
Stand by.
KIM:
I'm picking up
a transporter signature
300 kilometers
above the surface.
PARIS:
Captain, there's
a ship powering its engines
at those coordinates.
Magistrate, do you want us
to follow him?
Yes, but I'd like
to join you.
JANEWAY:
Very well. We'll beam you
to Voyager. Stand by.
( dramatic theme playing )
Kovin's ship is on a heading
of one-eight mark two-five.
Set an intercept course.
Get ready to lock on
a tractor beam.
He's only at
half impulse.
His ship may not have
warp engines.
We're at 9,000 kilometers
and closing.
I'm engaging
the tractor beam.
I can't find him.
All of my sensor readings
have disappeared.
He generated
a photonic pulse.
It took them off-line.
We'll have to reinitialize
the entire sensor array.
Do it.
( beeping )
Our investigation has suddenly
turned into a manhunt.
The fact that he's running shows
that he's got something to hide.
Until we find out what that is,
we can't risk letting him go.
( dramatic theme continues
playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
stardate 51679.4.
We've detected the warp
signature from Kovin's ship
and we're now in pursuit.
In the meantime,
Tuvok and I have been examining
the tools from Kovin's lab.
This isn't getting
us anywhere.
Seven's cellular residue
is on every one of these,
but that would be true
if she simply handled them.
My examination of the rifle
is equally inconclusive.
It may have overloaded
accidentally...
Or not.
I'm getting a bad feeling
about this, Tuvok.
We aren't finding anything
that implicates Kovin.
I told him
our investigation
would be impartial.
I believe it has been.
It has...
But I'll admit I had some
preconceptions about him.
They may have influenced
my judgment.
The strongest evidence
so far
is the nanoprobes
the doctor found.
The fact that they
were regenerated
suggests that Kovin
was experimenting with them.
We don't know a great deal
about the interaction
between nanoprobes
and Borg physiology.
It might be
worthwhile
to simulate the effect
of the rifle blast
on Seven's arm
and see what happens
to the nanoprobes.
Good.
Maybe that'll give us
some answers.
Is this really necessary,
Captain?
She's suffered
enough trauma already.
We don't want
to make accusations
against
an innocent man.
We have to do
everything we can
to find some
concrete evidence.
He is not
an innocent man.
I know
what he did to me.
But we must have
proof.
And this experiment
may provide us with it.
We've configured
this hypospray
to simulate the energy
of a thoron blast.
We'll collect thin layers
of your skin tissue
and examine the effects.
It won't be painful.
I am not afraid.
I am angry.
I know.
Try to be patient.
We may have
some answers soon.
All right,
let's see what we've got.
( dramatic theme playing )
I think you better
take a look.
What do you see?
The nanoprobes...
are regenerating
in exactly
the same pattern
we saw
in Kovin's laboratory.
It appears to be
a spontaneous response
which could have
been caused by
the energy released
from the thoron weapon.
It doesn't matter.
Kovin is guilty.
Seven...
there's no doubt
in my mind
that you believe
what you're saying,
but is it possible...
just possible...
That the memories you
and the doctor recovered
aren't accurate?
How could that be?
During your time
with the Borg,
you were subjected
to invasive
medical procedures.
You undoubtedly witnessed
other victims
being assimilated.
Could that be
what you're remembering?
You know that's not right.
Tell them.
Everything led me to believe
that you were a victim.
Your extreme response
to Kovin in engineering,
your irrational fear
when I was examining you...
Something prompted that
behavior, and I believed
it was a repressed memory
of your ordeal
with Kovin.
That is what it was.
But if I'm to be impartial,
I have to acknowledge
that your neurology is still
something of a mystery to me.
I can't be certain what
triggered those memories.
And we can't ignore
the fact
that this evidence supports
Kovin's story...
and not yours.
You were the one who helped me
to understand what happened
and now you're denying it.
Seven, no one's abandoning you,
but we have to do what's right.
We have to find Kovin
and tell him what we learned.
The doctor told me
I would feel better
when Kovin gets
what he deserves.
I want him
to be punished.
I won't settle for
anything less.
( dramatic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Mr. Paris.
He's in range.
Visual.
Hail him.
( beeping )
No response.
He's charging weapons.
Open a channel.
All frequencies.
Mr. Kovin,
this is Captain Janeway.
We believe we've made a mistake
in accusing you.
We only want to correct
the situation.
Stand down your weapons.
( machine beeps )
He's responding.
Stop your pursuit.
I can damage your ship.
We're not here
to take you by force.
Then let me go.
Kovin, listen to me.
The proceedings
must be resolved.
This is a trap.
JANEWAY: No.
We've discovered information
that supports your story.
I don't believe you.
We've reexamined
the evidence.
Finding the nanoprobes led us
to the wrong conclusion.
We know now that
your thoron rifle did overload.
DOCTOR:
Please...
( console beeping )
He's firing a spread
of photon pulses.
( crash )
Shields down
to 82 percent.
JANEWAY:
Back off. Give him some
breathing room.
He's coming about,
heading right for us.
Direct hit
to the power grid.
Innocent or not, he's going
to destroy your vessel.
Captain?
He's come under enough fire
from us already.
Harry, try to beam him
off his ship.
He's thrown up
a scattering field.
I can't get a lock.
Keep trying.
( crash )
Shields are down.
He's shunting all power
to his photonic emitters.
We must protect ourselves.
Disable his ship.
No. Evasive maneuvers,
hard to port, full thrusters.
Aye.
KIM:
I've almost got a lock on him.
A few more seconds.
He's charging weapons
again.
Captain,
his emitters are overloading.
All his systems
are destabilizing.
Open a channel.
Kovin, shut down
your scattering field.
Let us beam
you aboard.
Kovin!
He's firing.
( dramatic theme continues
playing )
Harry?
( console beeping )
I can't find anything
to lock onto, Captain.
( dramatic theme grows somber )
There's nothing more
we could have done.
Stand down red alert.
Mr. Paris, set a course
back to the Entharan colony.
( beeping )
DOCTOR:
Chief medical officer's log,
stardate 51658.2.
I've spent the past three days
being cross-examined
by the Entharan authorities,
but the matter
is finally resolved.
Doctor.
Yes.
I'm here for
my weekly maintenance.
Oh, of course.
This way, please.
Metabolic rate
is stable.
Electro-optic implant
is aligned.
Your blood pressure
is...slightly off,
but within tolerance.
You're in
perfect health.
See you next week.
I do not
feel perfect.
What do you mean?
I am preoccupied
by Kovin's death.
Join the club.
It's all
I can think about.
As a Borg,
I was responsible
for the destruction
of countless millions
and I felt nothing,
but now...
I regret the destruction
of this single being.
It's called remorse,
Seven.
It comes into play
when you make a mistake...
and you feel guilt
about what you've done.
Another new emotion
for you to experience.
I do not enjoy this remorse
any more than I enjoyed anger.
Will the feeling subside?
Yes, but not quickly.
I would rather
not have to wait.
I'm afraid
you don't have much choice.
( somber theme playing )
But maybe I do.
I've isolated the algorithms
responsible for my desire
to expand beyond
my original programming.
I want to delete them.
Why?
It was my...
urge to experiment,
my infatuation
with improving myself
that led to this tragedy.
I fancied myself a psychologist,
a ship's counselor,
but I wasn't prepared
for the complexities that come
with such
a responsibility.
In my enthusiasm
to help Seven of Nine,
I lost
my medical objectivity.
I became
a self-righteous advocate.
I didn't stop to think
for one second...
...that I might be wrong.
That mustn't happen again.
You want to go back
to the state you were in
when we first activated you?
I'll still be capable
of treating
any and all
medical conditions,
but without the risk
of overstepping my bounds.
It's for the best,
Captain.
Oh, I'm not so sure.
This crew has
benefited greatly
from your improvements
over the years.
Request denied.
Captain--
I won't turn back
the clock because of
one mistake,
no matter how serious...
...and no matter
how you might feel.
I'm a physician.
I'm supposed to preserve life,
not destroy it.
I can't live with
the thought that...
I might do it again.
With any luck...
...that knowledge will prevent
it from happening again.
We all rallied around Seven,
doctor, myself included.
I wanted her to know that
she was part of this family,
that we would support her,
fight for her,
no matter what.
We let our good intentions
blind us.
We all bear responsibility
for Kovin's death.
And we all
have to live with it.
But to delete that burden
would be the last thing
any of us should do.
( somber theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
( triumphant theme playing )