Pu'cha! Prepare
to meet your ancestors.
( grunting )
( dramatic theme playing )
( yelling )
This battle is yours today,
but the House of Mo'Kai
will never yield.
( yells )
DoH-cha Scree!
Move away, coward.
I want to make this kill.
You should have killed me
when my back was turned.
I want to see the
fear in your eyes.
Look closely and you'll
see your own destruction.
You are resilient prey.
I'm no one's prey!
( groaning )
You are mine now and after
death.
( com beeps )
Sickbay this is Holodeck 2.
Janeway requires
medical assistance.
( majestic theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
HIROGEN 1:
She'll survive.
HIROGEN 2:
What about her
neural interface?
Stable.
Are you sure?
There were times
when she seemed...
aware of who she is.
Impossible.
I was monitoring the crew
during the entire simulation.
She believes she's whoever
we program her to be.
Shall I return her
to the Klingon simulation?
No. Bring her to Holodeck 1.
I've found another program
I want to try.
A conflict that took place
on her own planet.
It should prove...
stimulating.
( piano playing slow jazz )
♪ Wrong ♪
♪ Would it be wrong to kiss ♪
♪ Seeing I feel like this? ♪
♪ Would it be wrong to try? ♪
♪ Wrong ♪
♪ Would it be wrong to stay ♪
♪ Here in your arms this way ♪
♪ Under this starry sky? ♪
♪ If it is wrong... ♪
Welcome to Le Coeur de Lion.
I'm Katrine.
The first round
is with my compliments
on one condition.
You leave the war outside.
More escargot
for table nine, hmm?
Jacques, no lady tonight?
Ha, ha. We'll have to see
what we can do about that.
Forgive my neglecting you.
Now, where were we?
Ah, yes, my latest
adventure in Paris.
♪ ...Wrong ♪
♪ When I need you so much... ♪
I'm afraid I have
to neglect you again.
Excuse me. Ha, ha.
♪ ...so long ♪
♪ It must be right... ♪
That's him.
Our new commandant?
British Intelligence believes
he's been sent here
to oversee the occupation
of the city.
JANEWAY:
What's his history?
TUVOK:
He served with Rommel
in North Africa
and Schmidt in Poland.
He is a formidable
military strategist,
notorious for
his cruelty.
Well, let's make him
feel at home.
Send him a bottle
of Chateau Latour.
My compliments.
The '29?
Oh, I hate to waste
good wine.
Give him the '36.
As you wish.
♪ ...And I have waited so long ♪
♪ It must be right ♪
♪ It can't be wrong ♪
( crowd clapping )
Merci.
Be generous to Claude
this evening.
Without him,
my voice is empty.
Good evening.
Sing.
Tonight's performance
is over. Return tomorrow.
Now.
Remove your hand.
Obey me,
or I will hunt you down
and your bones will adorn
the bulkhead of my ship.
Sit down and
play the game.
In this setting,
we have no ships.
We are an ancient
race of soldiers
intent upon
conquering this world.
Play the game.
Now, now. What's this?
Mademoiselle de Neuf
will be happy to
sing another song.
Just give her a few
minutes to freshen up.
It's late.
Freshen up.
Very well.
Commandant Karr.
You know me.
Your reputation precedes you.
I'm Katrine.
Le Coeur de Lion
is my establishment.
The first round
is with my compliments
on one condition.
You leave the war outside.
I wish to
speak with her...
alone.
Bon soir.
Charming gentleman.
He is disoriented.
Your world is
unfamiliar to him.
He'll be comfortable
soon enough.
The arms of France
are open to all.
I've heard otherwise.
What do you mean?
I understand
there is opposition
to our presence here
among your citizens.
The Resistance? Ha.
In Paris, perhaps,
but this is a small city,
defenseless.
We've learned to be
a little more diplomatic.
When this war is over,
we want to remain
on good terms with the victor.
Whoever that may be.
Your city may
be defenseless,
but it's crucial
to the war.
Any ground assault
into Germany
must pass through
this province.
The Resistance
will come here.
If they do, I'll tell them
what I tell everyone.
Leave the war outside.
Excellent.
Commandant, I've
been informed
there's a problem in
the Engineering section.
The warp plasma network
has become unstable.
What's he talking about?
It need not concern you.
To the hunt.
"The hunt"?
For the Resistance.
I shall take great pleasure
in tracking them down.
And making the kill.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Au revoir.
How'd we do?
Insufficient
for a Saturday night.
1,247 francs
and 81 Reichsmarks.
Well, it should be enough
to buy an oscillator
to extend the range
of our radio.
First thing tomorrow
morning, I want you
to take a little trip
to the countryside.
There's a Monsieur Groleau
who has a cottage
just past the third bridge.
He's got a wine cellar
full of vacuum tubes.
Tell him we need a high
frequency oscillator.
Offer him 300 francs,
but don't go any
higher than 500.
We have more pressing needs.
Such as?
Explosives. We need
a launcher that can fire
armor-piercing grenades.
Ha. Planning on blowing
up a German tank?
If necessary.
We're not trying
to build an army here.
Well, maybe it's time we did.
Three more German battalions
have occupied the city
and a panzer division
is holding position
11 kilometers away.
When the Americans arrive
and the fighting begins,
I don't intend to be standing
next to a piano
singing "Moonlight Becomes You."
The Americans won't
even be able
to approach this city
without our help.
And if they can't
liberate Sainte Claire,
the assault into
Germany could fail.
We need to be
gathering information
about German
troop movements
and relaying it
to Allied Command.
I'm tired of lighting
the Nazis' cigarettes
and laughing at their jokes.
We should be helping
the Allies
by assassinating these pigs.
The moment we
start shooting,
we expose ourselves.
Right now, no
one suspects us,
and I am not about to
risk our entire operation
because you've
suddenly developed
a nervous trigger finger.
That is your opinion, Madame.
I'm the leader
of the movement here,
and right now, my opinion
is the only one that counts,
so get the oscillator.
I think we're all
feeling the strain.
It's been a hard four years,
but believe me,
the Third Reich
is feeling it, too.
We just have to hang on
a little while longer.
Word from the Americans
is going to come any day.
Perhaps.
( door opens )
Again?
Again.
( door closes )
Why is she so adamant?
What she's proposing
would put us all at risk.
Maybe that's
her intention.
If you have suspicions,
my old friend,
let's hear them.
From the beginning,
she's been argumentative
and on more than
a few occasions,
she's disobeyed
your direct orders.
She's headstrong--
typical of the underground.
Nevertheless,
her behavior
has threatened
our identities.
She's the only
munitions expert we have
and she can carry a tune.
We need her.
Let's keep our eye on her.
Have her followed
for the next few days.
If she is
a Nazi infiltrator,
we'll have to eliminate her.
( suspenseful theme swells )
Bonjour, madame!
Bonjour, monsieur.
Put it on my account.
Whoo.
( chuckling )
Guten Tag.
You. Halt!
Get off
your vehicle.
What are you
transporting?
Nothing but
the very essentials of life.
Proceed to your
destination.
That I will.
That I most
certainly will.
If the choice
were mine,
you would already be dead.
( suspenseful theme playing )
MAN ( on radio ):
...all report rain.
It's currently
59 degrees in Dover
with low fog
across the Channel.
Temperatures are expected
to range
from a low of 45 degrees...
( static drowns out broadcast )
Damn, I'm missing it.
Our most recent
intelligence
shows two German armored
divisions here and here.
How recent is
this intelligence?
Forty-eight hours.
Old news.
( on radio ):
I am Reginald Smith,
and you're listening
to the British Radio Network.
This report will repeat in...
Forty-five seconds.
Here's to English precision.
( loud knocking )
( jazz music playing on radio )
We're closed.
NEELIX:
Morning delivery.
JANEWAY:
You're late. What happened?
Oh, just a little
tête-à-tête
with a member of
the Master Race.
That's the second
time this week.
Sound like they're
increasing their patrols.
Perhaps it's time
we chose another courier.
Our "baker"
is arousing suspicion.
There's no need
to worry.
I change my
route every day,
and I've become quite friendly
with most of the Gestapo.
They just love my strudel.
SMITH ( on radio ):
A kind thank you
to Jazzy McNulty and his band.
Now, the weather for today,
September 22, 1944.
In London, skies are gray
with a strong chance
of afternoon rain.
Temperatures will range
from a low of 52 degrees
to a high of 71.
The northern coast reports
heavy rain and strong winds
and ocean swells
reaching four feet.
Devonshire, Hertfordshire
and Sonnenshire
all report rain.
It's currently
59 degrees in Dover
with low fog
across the Channel.
Temperatures are expected to
range from a low of 45 degrees
to a high of 63.
I am Reginald Smith,
and you are listening...
( clicks button )
Got it.
Let's see the code key.
Every fifth letter,
every third vowel.
Use the Sunday
decryption sequence.
Mm-hmm.
JANEWAY:
"A..."
"H... C."
Straight from
Allied High Command.
It must be important.
All messages regarding
the war are important.
It's only a matter
of degree.
I suppose you're right,
but do you have to be so...
logical
about everything?
In any covert battle,
logic is a potent weapon.
You might try
it sometime.
"American Fourth Infantry...
to invade Sainte Claire...
Tuesday dawn."
That's two days
from now.
"Require assistance.
Disable enemy communications.
End message."
The German
radio transmitter
is housed at
their headquarters.
That building is
surrounded by guards.
We can't just waltz in
there and plant a bomb.
Maybe I can help.
How?
I'm upset.
I need to see
my special "friend..."
even if it means
bothering him at the office.
A reconnaissance
mission.
I'll try to locate
the radio,
see where the guards are posted,
examine the locks,
gather enough information
to get us inside.
It's too dangerous.
If you're caught,
you'll be tortured
for information.
You don't know my "friend."
He would never do anything
to harm his own child.
( soft theme playing )
Encode a response
to Allied Command.
Confirm that we've received
their message.
Tell them we're proceeding
according to plan.
( martial theme playing )
( conversing in French )
( spits )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( groans )
( both speaking German )
MAN:
Ever since my days
at the university,
I've admired this painting...
and now it's mine.
Our fellow officers
might prefer
gold or land,
but, for me, the greatest
prize of war is art.
Trophies of the hunt...
but was the hunt fair?
Sir?
We entered this city
with superior firepower
against a weakened prey.
Do you really deserve
these...prizes?
We are German.
The German people deserve Europe
and everything in it.
Why?
Sir...
You question our destiny?
Of course not,
but I want to hear it
in your own words.
Tell me. Why are
we the "Master Race"?
Our blood is pure.
Our people lived and hunted on
this land for a thousand years
before the degenerate races
brought their corruption.
Europe must be purified.
You, yourself...
are you stronger than
these "degenerate" races?
More cunning?
Yes, of course.
And if you were alone
without an army
supporting you,
would you continue
the hunt?
If your prey were armed
instead of defenseless,
what then?
I-- Colonel, I don't know
what you're trying--
You are superior
to no one!
Never underestimate your prey
or disrespect its abilities.
If you do,
you will become the hunted.
When the opposing army
invades this city,
remember my words.
( knocking )
Enter!
Brigitte!
I'm sorry.
I know I'm not
supposed to come here.
Don't blame him.
I told him I was ill,
that I had to see you.
I will leave
you two alone.
Heil Hitler.
It's all right.
The colonel is in
a strange mood today.
( gasping )
What's wrong?
Is it our child?
I don't know.
I was dizzy.
I'll call the doctor.
No!
I feel better now.
Maybe I just needed
to see you.
Why haven't you shown
me this place before?
I didn't want your neighbors
to see you coming here.
They make it
difficult enough for you,
knowing we're together.
I don't care
what they think.
It's beautiful.
Praxiteles, master sculptor
of ancient Greece.
There are only three
like this in all of Europe.
So many...
wonderful things.
( telegraph beeping )
( people chattering )
The commandant would
have us continue
this simulation
until we rot.
It's pointless.
We should
begin the hunt.
He believes we must learn
more about our prey,
but I have
learned enough.
Ready your weapon.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Avoid the cranium.
( grunting )
This way!
But-- The message!
There's no time.
( dramatic theme playing )
( whistle blowing )
( soldiers yelling in German)
Ah!
( both groan )
Computer,
exit holodeck.
We'll take them
to the medical bay.
( devices humming )
This neural interface
has been damaged.
That's because it
took a direct hit
when one of your bullets
grazed the base of her skull.
I'll provide you with
another-- install it.
Not until I've repaired
her injuries.
How long?
She has two
fractured vertebrae
and a punctured lung--
another hour at least.
Him?
I've stabilized
his vital systems,
but he still has
bullet fragments
lodged in his shoulder.
I will treat him.
This time, you might
do a better job
repairing
the muscle lacerations.
The last crew member
you treated
was brought back in
with internal bleeding.
Your crew is fragile.
They fall too easily.
What do you expect?
They've been stabbed,
shot, beaten, phasered
and bat'lethed over
the past three weeks.
Their bodies weren't designed
for this kind of punishment.
What happened?
These prey were
hunted by Turanj.
Their injuries
are severe.
You assured me
that your people
would avoid causing
serious head injuries.
Another centimeter
and the bullet would have
penetrated her brain.
If you can't keep
your people under control,
then you should put an end
to this blood sport.
The simulations will continue.
At least activate the holodeck
safety protocols.
No.
It'll prevent
life-threatening injuries,
for your people as well.
It will also eliminate
the challenge.
I have had 28 wounded
and one fatality
in the past 12 hours.
Even I can't keep up
with that level of triage.
You will keep up
or they will die.
Their lives are in
your hands, doctor.
Don't fail them.
( suspenseful theme playing )
When that one is ready,
place him in Holodeck 2.
Let's see how he fares
with the Klingons.
What about her?
Send her back to Holodeck 1.
I like her voice.
( consoles beeping )
Progress?
By cutting through the bulkheads
on Decks 4, 5 and 6,
we've been able to expand
both holodeck grids
by 5,000 square meters.
More.
( sighs )
I can't give you any more.
Not without compromising
Voyager's primary systems.
Then compromise them.
Look, holodecks require
a tremendous amount of energy.
I've already rerouted power
from all nonessential systems.
Anything more, and we'll start
losing propulsion, deflectors
even life support.
I'll transfer a supply
of power nodules from my vessel.
Integrate them
into your systems.
I want to expand
the holo-projectors
into all surrounding sections.
Replicate enough emitters
for the task.
Yes, sir.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( grunts )
( sighs )
( devices beeping )
The holo-emitters
in this corridor are stable.
Let's start working
on Section 19.
( quietly ):
But first, tell the guard
to escort you to Engineering.
That we need more equipment.
Specifically, a type-3
isolinear emitter.
If he gives you any trouble,
say "I can't complete
the assignment without it."
We need an isolinear
emitter from Engineering.
( beeping )
Ensign, how did
I get here?
I transferred you here
using the new emitters
in this section.
I assume you've
got a plan?
Half a plan.
Let's hear it.
Before we can
retake the ship,
we've got to get
the crew back.
And that means disabling
the neural interfaces.
Easier said than done.
The great hunters are
everywhere you turn.
Don't worry.
I think I've found
a way to tap
into the Sickbay
diagnostic console.
The only catch is--
( whoosh )
Stand by with the emitter.
I'm almost done here.
The catch, Ensign?
Somebody's got to be
inside the holodeck
to engage the
Bridge control relays.
We're shorthanded.
I know.
Well, we've got a Borg
on board, don't we?
Maybe we can put her
to good use.
( suspenseful theme calming )
I have been studying
Voyager's database
looking for our
next simulation.
There are many
to choose from.
These people have
a violent history.
I believe I've found
a worthy prey:
the Borg.
When World War II is over,
we will recreate
a notorious battle
known as "Wolf 359."
I look forward to it.
I thought you might, but if you
continue to disobey me,
this is one hunt
you will never see.
You nearly destroyed
two of my favored prey.
You were careless.
I've become impatient.
We penetrated this vessel,
overcame their defenses
and in the moment of the kill,
you forced us to stop.
Now we play
these incessant games.
It's time we took our trophies
and moved on.
Your lust for the kill
has blinded you
like many young hunters.
If you took the time
to study your prey,
to understand its behavior,
you might learn something.
There is nothing to be learned.
You're wrong.
Each prey exposes us
to another way of life
and makes us reevaluate
our own.
Have you considered
our future?
What will become of us
when we have hunted this
territory to exhaustion?
We will travel
to another part of space,
search for new prey
as we have always done.
A way of life that hasn't
changed for a thousand years.
Why should it?
Species that don't change...
die.
We've lost our way.
We've allowed our
predatory instincts
to dominate us.
We disperse ourselves
throughout the Quadrant,
sending ships
in all directions.
We've become
a solitary race, isolated.
We've spread ourselves
too thin.
We're no longer a culture.
We have no identity.
In another thousand years,
no one will remember
the name "Hirogen."
Our people must
come back together,
combine forces,
rebuild our civilization.
What of the hunt?
The hunt will
always continue
but in a new way.
I intend to transform
this ship
into a vast simulation
populated with a varied
and endless supply of prey.
In time, this technology
can be duplicated
for other Hirogen.
These holodecks will allow us
to hold onto our past
while we face the future.
Even if I were persuaded,
others wouldn't be.
Then you are with me.
I must continue
my research.
I'll see you tomorrow
on Holodeck 1.
The Americans are due
to invade.
( suspenseful theme swells )
Remain calm
and stay quiet.
There's a Hirogen
working in the bio-lab.
He might hear us.
What's the last
thing you remember?
An attack.
The Hirogen vessels.
They breached our hull
and boarded the ship.
I was in a phaser fight
on Deck 3.
I was struck several times.
That's all I remember.
Then you have no memory
of the simulations
in the holodeck?
None.
The neural interface
must be circumventing
your memory centers.
Neural interface?
It's a subdermal
transmitter
that links your neocortex
to the holodeck.
In essence, it
makes you believe
you're a character
within the program.
Why am I in Sickbay?
You were wounded
in the simulation.
It's my job to patch you
all up and send you back in.
Half the crew is
under lock and key.
The rest are fighting for
their lives on the holodeck.
This has been going
on for 19 days--
dozens of battle scenarios,
one more brutal
than the next.
You should see what a mess
you were after the Crusades.
Will I be sent
into another simulation?
Yes, but this time...
with an advantage.
I have found a way
to disable the interface
by remodulating
one of your Borg implants
to emit a jamming signal.
Once the Hirogen have brought
you back to the holodeck,
the jamming signal
will activate within seconds.
My objective?
You must find a control panel
inside the holodeck
and engage
the Bridge access relays.
That will enable
Ensign Kim and me
to deactivate
all the neural interfaces.
After Captain Janeway
and the crew regain awareness,
you can work with them
to mount a resistance
against the Hirogen.
What simulation
will I be entering?
World War II--
a 20th century Earth conflict.
Do you know anything
about it?
Nothing.
That could
be a problem.
Once the interface is disabled,
you won't remember anything
about your role
in the simulation.
Think of it
as a new social setting.
Do your best to fit in.
This is the last
neural interface.
When you've
finished with her,
you'll help me
replicate more.
I have to sedate you now.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( sighs )
( piano playing
slow accompaniment )
♪ That old black magic
Has me in its spell ♪
That you weave so well ♪
♪ Those icy fingers
Up and down my spine ♪
♪ The same old witchcraft
When your eyes meet... ♪
( soft clicking )
( piano stops playing )
I must discontinue
this activity.
I am not well.
( piano playing up-tempo solo )
If the entertainment
is over, I'll be going.
Stay right
there, Commandant.
I'm sure she's fine.
Let me talk to her.
What's wrong?
I require
a glass of water.
Make it a quick one.
I promised the commandant
you'd be singing
till midnight.
I want to get a lot of
information out of him tonight.
I am ill.
Look, I don't care
if you're dying.
Get back out there.
I won't.
Maybe you're right about her.
The evidence is increasing.
She was present today
when our courier was
shot down in the street,
yet somehow,
she was unharmed.
And now, on the eve
of our liberation,
she becomes
uncooperative.
Leave this to me.
( majestic theme playing )
Captain...
At ease.
What's the word?
There is no word, at least
not from the Resistance
in Sainte Claire.
Then we won't get any support
from inside the city.
You may be underestimating
the good citizens
of Sainte Claire.
I spent a summer there
when I was 18.
Let me guess.
You ate a few snails, fell
in love with a local girl
and became an expert
on the city.
Uh, well, ah.
Yeah, pretty much like that.
I see.
But believe me, Captain,
those people love their town.
They'll fight for it
and die for it.
Don't count them out yet.
All right,
but I won't count
them in, either.
We continue as planned--
an assault from the north
at first light.
( sighs )
So, who was the mademoiselle?
( laughs )
Her name was Brigitte.
Great gams.
One hell of a temper.
Sounds like your kind of girl.
August 29, 1936...
12:17 P.M.
That's when my train
pulled out of Sainte Claire.
That's the last time I saw her.
We wrote to each other
every week for three years.
Then the war broke out,
and I never heard
from her again.
Sainte Claire's not a big place.
She shouldn't be
too hard to find.
Heh. I'm counting on it.
JANEWAY:
You'll maintain position here,
20 meters from the front doors.
Arm yourself with
a submachine gun,
and watch for any
sign of trouble.
Understood.
Now, we've observed
a 20-second break
in the guard rotation
at 4:15 A.M.
That should give you
and me enough time
to enter the building
through the storm window
on the eastern wall.
When I was there yesterday,
I saw guards posted
at all three stairways.
So you'll have to reach
the second floor
through the
elevator shaft.
The command post is
in the main gallery
at the end of the hall.
Once inside, we
plant the charges,
load the transmitter.
You'll remain here.
If something goes wrong
and we're caught,
destroy all evidence
of the underground--
our contact lists,
decryption codes-- everything.
Right.
We leave in one hour.
( door opens and closes)
This won't make
much of a bang.
You forgot to connect
the detonator.
I will correct the error.
It's lucky I found
your little error.
It might have
undermined our mission.
Are you having second
thoughts about tonight?
No.
Good, because I don't
want any more mistakes.
There won't be any.
Let's hope not.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( beeping )
( sighs )
We've got to stop
meeting like this.
I managed to grab
a quick scan of Holodeck 1,
and it looks like
Seven of Nine is on the move.
Are you ready in Sickbay?
My Hirogen taskmaster is
working in the bio-lab.
I'll have access to
the medical console
for another 20
minutes at least.
That'll give me enough time
to get to the Bridge and--
( door opens )
( beeps )
Good afternoon.
What are you
doing in here?
Trying to get the replicator
system back on line...
unless you prefer
the emergency rations.
Personally, I'm getting
tired of synthetic protein.
You're supposed to be the
finest hunters in the Quadrant.
Why don't you find us
something a little more tasty?
Something wrong?
An unauthorized transmission
was sent from this room.
What kind of transmission?
I don't know.
Maybe you can tell me.
Well...I was trying
to reroute power
from the main computer
to the replicators.
Oh, of course.
I must have tripped
a communications subroutine.
Sorry about that.
Didn't mean to worry you.
Your people have damaged
just about every system
on this vessel.
Accidents are bound to happen.
Now, if you don't mind,
I'm due on the Bridge.
Show it to me.
What?
I want to see
this subroutine.
Show me what you were doing
when the "accident" occurred.
Forget it.
I don't have time.
( groaning )
Do as I say.
All right!
( panting )
But you'd better
call the Bridge.
Tell your superior
I'm going to be late--
that I'm working
under your orders now, not his.
Go ahead.
Make the call.
I don't want to take the blame
for this.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Report to the Bridge.
Thanks.
( crickets chirping )
( engines revving )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( telegraph beeping )
( beeping continues )
( suspenseful theme
continues playing )
( both grunt )
Set the charges here,
here and there.
This looks like a message
from one of their
reconnaissance teams.
These must be instructions
for troop deployments.
The Germans must be taking up
new positions outside the city.
It looks like
they're mobilizing
more troops than our sources
originally expected.
( clicking )
( beeping )
They're moving armored units
into the valley.
They must know
the Americans are coming.
We've got to warn them somehow.
( clicking )
What are you doing?
You haven't set the charges.
What is that?
I believe it is a transmitter.
I'm attempting to disable it.
You're sending a message
to the Nazis.
No.
Step away
or I'll kill you.
What are you doing?
Uh, nothing. Just
running a diagnostic...
You've accessed
the neural interface controls.
Stop it immediately.
I told you. No more mistakes.
You've just made
your last one.
( beeping )
( clicking )
( gasping )
Seven.
Captain.
( distant howling )
Listen.
( howling )
A targ.
Just beyond that ridge.
You would hunt down
a simple beast
even in the midst
of our enemies?
There is no enemy
as great as hunger!
( com beeps )
Why am I being
interrupted?
The holographic Doctor--
he's disabled their
Captain's interface.
How?
I don't know, but I can't
reestablish the link.
Send a team to Holodeck 1.
Remove her from the simulation.
( martial theme playing )
Hirogen hunters.
Internal scans show 13 of them
on this holodeck.
( glass shattering )
CHAKOTAY:
Need a hand, buddy?
Captain Miller,
Fifth Armored Infantry.
Welcome to
Sainte Claire.
Get me Artillery
Unit Charlie One.
Take up positions
along this street
and start laying down fire.
( air raid sirens )
The Americans have arrived.
You circumvented
our control!
How?
Go to hell!
MAN:
Spread out!
( distant gunfire )
( air raid sirens )
( voices in distance )
( suspenseful theme
continues playing )
Bobby.
( sighs )
You owe me a postcard.
Distance: 800 yards. Correct
for crosswinds. Fire at will.
Take cover, boys!
Charlie One isn't
known for accuracy!
I can't access
the ship's systems.
Didn't you say this
was Nazi headquarters?
I did.
Then it would stand to reason
this building is being targeted.
Let's get out of here.
( incoming mortar flying )
( both grunt )
What happened?
There was a simulated explosion
in Holodeck 1.
Somehow it blew out the
holo-grid across three decks.
Is the program
still running?
Yes.
( men shouting in distance )
( suspenseful theme
continues playing )
( gasping )
What is it?
It looks like a bunker.
All units, listen up.
We've just blown the lid
off of some kind
of secret Nazi compound.
Converge on my position.
We're going in.
The breach opened the simulation
into the surrounding sections.
I'm picking up holographic
soldiers moving onto Deck 5.
Shut down the holo-emitters
until we can regain control.
I can't. The program
controls are off-line.
You wanted a war?
Looks like you've got one.
( martial theme playing )
( gunfire continues )
MAN:
Take your positions
on the double.
All right, sir.
Circle to the left.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )