ANNOUNCER:
Last time
on Star Trek Voyager...
You are resilient prey.
I'm no one's prey!
Aah.
KLINGON 1:
She'll survive.
KLINGON 2:
What about her
neural interface?
Stable.
Shall I return her
to the Klingon simulation?
No.
Bring her to
Holodeck 1.
I've found another program
I want to try.
♪ Here in your arms
This way... ♪
I'm Katrine.
Le Coeur de Lion
is my establishment.
The commandant
would have us
continue this simulation
until we rot.
It's pointless.
We should begin
the hunt.
We've been able to expand
both holodeck grids
by 5,000 square meters.
More.
The colonel is
in a strange mood today.
( dramatic theme playing )
( both grunt )
I have found a way
to disable the interface
by remodulating
one of your Borg implants
to emit a jamming signal.
You circumvented
our control!
How?
You're sending a message
to the Nazis.
No.
Step away
or I'll kill you.
Need a hand, buddy?
Captain Miller,
Fifth Armored Infantry.
Welcome to
Sainte Claire.
This building
is being targeted.
Let's get out of here.
( grunts )
You wanted a war?
Looks like
you've got one.
ANNOUNCER:
And now the conclusion.
( dramatic theme playing )
( gunfire )
Come on. Move up.
Looks like the Hirogen
have been busy.
This entire section
has been equipped
with holo-emitters.
Let's get to Astrometrics.
( door opens )
( grunts )
There are 85
Hirogen on board
concentrated
on Decks 2 through 9.
What about the Bridge?
Four Hirogen
and Ensign Kim.
At least he's alive.
The neural interfaces--
you said they're controlled
through Sickbay.
Yes. There's only one
Hirogen in Sickbay
with the doctor,
but the corridors
outside are
heavily guarded.
That's our first objective--
disable the interfaces--
but we'll need help.
We did have allies in the
World War II simulation--
the French Resistance.
It's time we mount
a resistance of our own.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )
KIM:
The battle is concentrated
here in Holodeck 1,
but the fighting has spilled
out onto Decks 5 and 6.
And it looks like a group
of holographic Americans
is invading Deck 7.
Show me the breach
in the hologrid.
( static )
I've lost the visual link.
It was the last active circuit
connecting the Bridge
to the holodecks.
There's only one way
to stop this.
I need to go to Engineering
and initiate a power surge
across the holo-emitter
network.
It'll blow out
the entire system.
No. That would destroy
both the holodecks.
Look, simulation or not,
if this battle keeps going
we could all be killed.
I want that technology
preserved.
Commander.
Status.
I was able
to reach Deck 5,
but holographic forces
are massing near the breach.
If I'm to get into the holodeck,
I'll need help.
Take the hunters
from the Klingon simulation.
When I find Captain Janeway,
should I kill her?
No.
Bring her to me.
This is no longer a game.
This hunt is real.
We should kill the prey.
The Voyager crew must
remain alive to make repairs
or we could lose everything--
this vessel, its technology.
You said that you understood
the importance
of what we're doing here.
I'll get the hunters.
( gunfire outside )
We think it's a secret
compound the Nazis built
after they took
over the city.
What I don't understand
is how they managed
to camouflage it so well.
Indeed.
We've been scrutinizing
German troop movements
since the occupation.
We knew nothing
of this installation.
Don't sweat it.
Our recon planes
missed it, too.
Any idea what they're
hiding in there, Captain?
We saw all sorts of scientific
equipment-- strange metals,
instruments we can't identify.
I've relayed the findings
to Military Intelligence.
They believe this
could be an advanced
munitions laboratory
designed to build
some kind of superweapon.
We've got to put it
out of business.
I've already sent
three squads in,
but the Nazis are putting up
one hell of a fight.
I've requested
additional troops.
Lieutenant,
this restaurant will serve
as our command post.
Set up the transmitter
and post guards
around the perimeter.
Yes, sir.
You've done
a bang-up job,
but we'll take it
from here.
Tell your people
to lie low
and that the Americans
said "thanks."
This is our city.
We have no intention
of lying low.
Listen, honey,
the time
for sneaking messages
back and forth is over.
This is war,
and you aren't soldiers.
He's right.
We have weapons hidden
throughout the city.
Brigette will tell
you where they are.
Sounds good.
Lieutenant, take care of it.
I can see you
haven't changed.
Bring me one
of those street maps.
Most of the guns, we stole
from the German army.
The explosives, we bought
from the black market.
We could use both.
Our biggest stockpile
is buried here--
two meters beneath
the last row of seats
of the Cinema Mystère.
You remember it,
don't you?
Hmm.
I'm No Angel
with Mae West.
There's heavy fighting
in that area.
What's the best way in?
We dug a tunnel that leads
directly to the stockpile.
Here. I'll show you.
Incidentally...
we saw
Death Takes a Holiday.
It was the Mae West movie.
I'm sure of it.
She was singing...
"Sister Honky Tonk,"
and I put my arm around you.
And during
the courtroom scene...
I kissed you.
You know,
I think you're right.
I guess the experience wasn't
exactly burned into your memory.
Not the movie.
But I do remember the kiss.
So...
did you get my last letter?
You mean the one asking
me to leave France?
Germany was
about to invade.
I thought you'd be safer
back in the States...with me.
But...I guess
you found someone else
to take care of you.
There's never been
anybody else.
Then who...?
He's second
in command
of the Sainte Claire
occupation.
The first time he saw me,
he said I was pretty.
I took advantage
of his interest.
He doesn't know
I'm in the Resistance.
The child is his.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
( metallic clank )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hold your fire.
Katrine...
you survived.
Are you surprised?
Very. Nazi headquarters
was destroyed.
We assumed you were killed
in the explosion.
What is that?
Some kind of
an escape tunnel?
That's precisely
what it is.
You're the leader of
the local Resistance.
That's right.
Captain Miller
Fifth Armored Infantry.
This is Lieutenant Davis.
I take it you've seen the
German bunker we uncovered.
I just came from there.
We suspect it's a munitions lab.
Can you confirm that?
Yes. A munitions lab.
Then this is it.
We're calling in
an air strike.
Contact the RAF.
Hold on, Captain.
There's an easier way
to do this
with a minimum
of casualties.
Let's hear it.
I've located the generator
that powers the entire complex.
It's heavily guarded,
but with your help,
I can get close enough
to set off some explosives.
My orders are to blow
the entire compound
before the Germans
send in reinforcements.
I saw technology in there
you can't begin to imagine--
warheads powerful enough
to destroy this entire valley
if they're
accidentally detonated.
Call for an air strike,
may be the last call you make.
How can you get close enough?
This tunnel.
I've been watching
this compound
for several months,
and I've got a man inside.
The place is crawling
with Krauts.
That's why I need your help.
If your men can clear
these two corridors,
it'll give us access
to this entryway.
Get me there,
and I can take care of the rest.
"C" Company--
what's their status?
They're holding position
about 200 yards from here.
Get them on the horn.
You'll lead us
into the compound,
but I'm coming
with you.
I work better alone.
This isn't a request.
It's an order.
Order? Do I look like I'm
wearing one of your uniforms?
I go alone.
I thought you
needed our help.
I'll be right
behind you.
PARIS ( outside ):
Lieutenant Blake.
There's been
a change of plans...
( voice continues
indistinctly )
Even if I manage to disrupt
the neural interfaces,
we've still got
a war to fight.
We're going to need something
a lot more effective
than these old firearms.
I believe I can enhance
these weapons
using Borg technology,
but I'll have
to access Cargo Bay 2.
If something goes wrong
and I don't succeed,
you'll be the only one left
who knows what's
really going on.
Understood.
( bombs exploding outside )
Have our suspicions
been confirmed?
Suspicions?
Is she a collaborator?
I think we
can trust her.
Are you certain?
Three hours ago,
you were prepared
to put a bullet in her head.
She's on our side.
In your absence,
I may be forced to make
that determination for myself.
I've already made it.
You're not to harm her.
Is that understood?
( German voices approaching )
( dramatic theme playing )
German forces are advancing
on our position.
Let's give them
a warm welcome.
Mademoiselle, after you.
Punctured lung,
arterial rupture,
fracture of the 13th vertebrae.
He needs surgery.
First and second-degree burns
to the face and neck.
Treat him.
His injuries are minor.
He can wait.
I said treat him!
This man has
massive internal injuries.
If I don't operate now,
he'll die.
Treat the burns, or I'll
deactivate your program.
What kind
of physician are you?
The first rule of triage
states that critical injuries
take priority.
Your rules, not mine.
From now on, leave the wounded
prey where they fall.
Tend only to our own.
I'm as dry
as the crater at Tarpahk...
( chuckling )
...in the middle
of the dry season...
when it's dry!
( laughing hysterically )
( grunts )
I'm not done!
Share with your brothers.
It's the eve of battle.
( grunts )
( roars )
I may be drunk,
but I can still send your soul
to the next world
and leave your body here
to rot!
Though from the stench of it,
I'd say it's begun to already.
( chuckles )
( grunts )
( laughing )
( distant gunfire )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( bullet being chambered )
( gunshots )
Tom. Ha.
Wrong guy.
You speak English?
Yeah.
I speak English.
American?
I didn't see him coming.
You saved my life.
Why are you
out of uniform?
What company are you with?
Um...
well, I'm a...I'm a civilian.
In the middle
of a battle zone in France?
The hell you are.
( gunfire )
Go on.
I'm right behind you.
Look, I don't have time
for 20 questions.
You say you're an American?
All right then, if Betty Grable
came around that corner
what part of her
would you be staring at?
Sorry. Time's up.
Her legs!
I-I'd be staring at her legs.
( nervous chuckle )
Ha. Bull's-eye.
Lucky for you.
( sighs )
You're a gung ho kind
of gal, aren't ya?
Does that bother you?
Nope. Just not used
to it, that's all.
The girls back home
are a little different.
I guess when it comes
to my people's safety,
this girl tends to get
a little...gung ho.
Nothing to
apologize for.
I'm the same way
with my men.
There's not
a day goes by
when I don't
think to myself,
"I'm going to get
'em back safely
even if I die trying."
I know the feeling.
We're about to enter some caves
that run under the town.
Caves?
We're going to meet our contact
there. I should warn you.
There are eccentric people
who live in the caves,
but don't be alarmed.
( suspenseful theme playing )
NEELIX &amp; KLINGONS:
♪ ...ro-cha loH qech ♪
♪ Ro-cha loH qech ♪
♪ Qor'taH-taH-taH-taH-
TaH-taH-taH Dech roH ♪
♪ TaH-taH-taH-taH-taH-taH ♪
♪ Dech roH! ♪
Good evening,
gentlemen.
Who are you?
How did you get past
our battle lines?
We're friends.
Allies.
Sent by what House?
The House of...
...of ToH-Maag.
ToH-Maag.
I never heard of it.
I'm not surprised.
It's a long
way from here.
This battle
doesn't concern you.
Maybe not...
but we'd be honored
to fight alongside
such great warriors.
If you prefer, we'll take
our weapons elsewhere.
Wait!
I'll consider your request...
but first, prove your fortitude.
Drink!
San-roH
t'patoH-cha!
I guess my French
is a little rusty.
( quietly ):
Don't drink it.
It's twice as
strong as whiskey.
I'll be right back.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( chuckling ):
Eh?
( Neelix continues
indistinctly )
Captain. Is--
Is it you?
Yes. We've got to disable
the rest of those interfaces.
The controls are routed
through the surgical
console in Sickbay,
but it will take time
to disable all of them.
We don't have time.
I'll access the Jefferies tube
that runs under that deck plate,
set a few charges
and blow out the console.
Charges? The Hirogen
have seized the armories.
No problem.
I got all the ammo I need
right here.
Holographic explosives?
With the safety protocols
off-line,
they're as good
as the real thing.
Hmm.
( muttering )
Ah! Another
of your warriors?
Yes.
He's a frail-looking thing.
I'll contact you
when I've disabled
the rest of the interfaces.
In the meantime, stay here.
With the Klingons?
Believe me,
it's peaceful
compared to
Sainte Claire.
Captain.
( growls )
( yells )
Please, don't do that.
( sinister chuckle )
( dramatic theme playing )
( explosion )
They've got us
outnumbered!
And outgunned.
They're setting up a machine gun
emplacement across the street.
Where have you been?
Obtaining supplies.
What is this?
German technology taken
from their compound.
I can use them to
enhance our weapons.
( automatic gunfire, yelling)
I've cornered several
Voyager crewmen,
but they've taken refuge
in a guarded building.
I need three nucleonic charges
to penetrate the structure.
Nucleonic charges could damage
the holodeck further.
Use your hand weapons.
Then I'll need
more hunters.
They're on the way.
Damn. There's
a level-9 force field
around the surgical
console.
We'll have to go in
and shut it down.
"Force field"?
I'll explain later.
Set the detonator
for five minutes.
( ticking )
Five hunters have been killed
in the last hour.
You must engage
the safety protocols.
Those protocols
aren't functioning.
Then I'll need
assistance to...
( hatch opens )
Stand by.
You.
Get him out of here.
There are ten pounds of
dynamite under the floor
set to blow in less
than three minutes.
Move.
Bridge to Sickbay.
Sickbay, respond.
Bridge to Deck 5.
Converge on the Sickbay.
( dramatic theme playing )
( yells )
( groans )
( ticking )
Ow!
Oh!
( all groaning )
( panting )
We're on the holodeck
under attack.
You must--
( dramatic theme playing )
Bridge,
this is Holodeck 1.
I have seized the building
and I have found
another access to this holodeck.
Seal it. How many captives?
Four. Their neural interfaces
have been disabled.
I will make the kill.
No. They are not prey.
They are hostages.
I'll need them.
As you wish.
You. Help me seal this hatch.
So, what do you think?
A boy or a girl?
It's a holographic
projection.
Unfortunately,
it's a very good projection.
I feel 20 kilos heavier.
It even kicks.
I don't recognize
this program.
I do.
He's wearing a Nazi uniform.
We're on Earth
during the second world war.
"Nazi"?
Totalitarian fanatics
bent on world conquest--
the Borg of their day,
no offense.
None taken.
What are you staring at?
Get up.
You deceived me.
Really?
I should've seen through
your flirtations.
If you say so.
The thought of you
carrying my child disgusts me.
You're not the only one.
Look, I don't know
what went on
between the two of you,
but it's obviously over now.
I see you're acquainted.
Do you find her as attractive
as I once did?
I'll miss our nights together.
Pig!
Put the weapon away.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Now.
Funny. He doesn't
seem like your type.
Doctor, trouble.
Now what?
The Klingons are starting
to wake up from their nap.
All right, hold on.
What are you doing?
I've established an interface
with Holodeck 1.
I want to monitor
what's going on over there
in case the crew
needs my help.
KLINGON:
Qapla'!
( quietly ):
Uh-oh. What should we do?
Not having a cure
for Klingon hangovers,
I couldn't tell you.
The battle has begun.
Our plan is to penetrate
the enemy's position,
cut his forces in half.
And a very good plan it is.
Best of luck with it.
You...
will lead us into
battle, great warrior.
Maybe I'll just watch
from here.
Try to offer up some pointers
as things develop.
To'qaH! Lead the attack
or die here by my hand.
You heard him. Don't argue
with the man. Run along.
I'll reattach any severed limbs.
Just don't misplace them.
You! Cover our flank.
Qapla'!
Qapla'.
Tallyho.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( door chimes )
Enter.
Leave her.
I see you've done
some redecorating.
Your attempt
to retake this vessel was...
inventive.
From the day I seized
Voyager, you put up
a dauntless fight,
but your fight is over now.
You're going to help me
shut down these simulations
and repair the holodecks.
No.
We'll destroy this ship
before we surrender it.
Don't threaten me,
Captain.
I've faced far more
intimidating prey than you.
If this fight continues,
I promise you,
I will hunt down and kill
every member of your crew.
Well, by then this ship
will be damaged beyond repair
and there won't be much
of a trophy left, will there?
Perhaps I should kill you
and find someone who
will cooperate.
Good luck.
You'll get the same response
from all of them.
You don't realize
what's at stake.
I know what's at stake--
your sick little game.
This is not a game!
Then what is it?
I'm trying to create a future
for my people.
Future?
I don't expect you
to understand.
You are prey.
You underestimate us.
Yes.
Perhaps I do.
I'm listening.
My people are hunting
themselves into extinction.
Your holodeck technology
might offer us
an alternative--
a new way of life.
Instead of scattering ourselves
across the Quadrant
in pursuit of prey,
we could simulate the hunt
and give ourselves a chance
to rebuild our civilization.
And confine your killing
to holograms.
With the safety protocols
off-line, the pursuit is just
as challenging.
Oh, I understand
what you're trying to do,
but then...why have
you been torturing us?
Why have you thrown my crew
into one brutal
simulation after another?
I've been studying
your behavior
as I do with all my prey,
but your holodecks
allowed me to go further--
to explore your culture,
your history.
I must admit
I've learned a great deal.
How so?
Your people have faced
extinction many times,
but you've always
managed to avoid it.
You seem to recognize
the need for change.
Yes. You've got one
of those moments
running right now
on the holodeck.
We called it World War II.
One of your
most difficult eras.
And yet you survived.
It wasn't easy.
You are a resilient species.
I admire your cunning.
Let's end this.
I'll call a cease-fire
and we can try
to contain the damage.
I want my ship back,
but in return, I will give you
what you need to create
the holodeck technology.
It would be cunning
for you to agree.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Synthetic.
And undrinkable.
I am tired of
this simulation.
Mein Herr,
a word with you.
And these holograms
are becoming annoying as well.
What are we waiting for?
Why don't we execute
these prisoners?
Orders from the commandant.
If I may speak freely?
The commandant has been acting
strangely the past few days.
He's been questioning
German superiority.
Perhaps we shouldn't follow
his orders so...
blindly.
You will do as he says...
as long as I tell you to.
I don't know how much longer
I can stand
being trapped in here.
Perhaps you would enjoy
some entertainment.
Sing.
I will not.
Sing...
or you will die.
Then I'll die.
Seven, you are
a valued member
of this crew.
The logical response
would be to grant
his request.
Logic is irrelevant.
One day the Borg
will assimilate your species
despite your arrogance.
When that moment arrives,
remember me.
ALPHA-HIROGEN ( on com ):
Bridge to Holodeck 1.
Yes.
I've come to an agreement
with Captain Janeway.
Call a cease-fire.
What?
Captain...?
JANEWAY ( on com ):
It's true, Tuvok.
Our first order
of business
is to call
off the troops.
I want you
to find Chakotay
and have him
convince his soldiers
to pull out of the city.
Aye, Captain.
Turanj, order our hunters
to end the fighting.
This is madness.
We're winning
this battle.
Our civilization depends
on this agreement.
Acknowledged.
You heard him.
Release the captives.
I'll tell the others.
Order all units
to withdraw
to these positions.
I have always thought
highly of you.
Have you?
Yes.
But the commandant
is a fool.
He doesn't understand.
He's never embraced
the Fuhrer...or his vision.
One does not cooperate
with decadent forms of life.
One hunts them down
and eliminates them.
The commandant speaks
of civilization.
The ancient Romans
were civilized.
The Jews are civilized.
But in all its moral
decay, Rome fell
to the spears
of our ancestors...
as the Jews are falling now.
Look
at our destiny.
The field of red.
The purity of German blood.
The blazing white
circle of the sun
that sanctified
that blood.
No one can deny us,
no power on Earth or beyond--
not the Christian savior,
not the God of the Jews.
We are driven by the very force
that gives life
to the universe itself.
We must countermand
the commandant's orders.
Stay and fight.
We must be faithful
to who we are.
( suspenseful theme playing )
You two, follow me.
CHAKOTAY:
All units,
clear the valley.
Return to your
previous positions.
We're calling
a cease-fire.
Repeat. Cease-fire.
Well, the word is out.
Whether it will be acted upon
is another question.
Oh, they'll follow orders.
I'm their commanding officer,
remember?
Keep it moving!
Get the lead out of your pants!
SOLDIER:
Yes, sir. You heard him!
Let's move it.
( chuckles )
Mid-20th century
American slang.
You got a problem
with that, sister?
You're enjoying
this simulation.
I find that peculiar,
given the circumstances.
Loosen up, baby doll.
The war's almost over. Aah!
( rapid gunfire )
( dramatic theme playing )
So much for
the cease-fire!
Fire! Fire!
I've been monitoring
the other simulation,
and the fighting's
getting worse.
The crew is taking
heavy casualties.
How can we help?
I'll transfer my program
to Holodeck 1.
You take the Jefferies tube
and meet me there.
There's only
the two of us.
Nevertheless, we have to try--
( loud belch )
Even half drunk,
Klingons are among the best
warriors in the galaxy.
But they're already
in the middle of a war
with the House of...
mmm, uh, whatever it is.
Then you'll just have
to convince them
that there's a more important
battle to be waged.
What, me?
You are their "great
warrior." Lead them.
( clears throat )
Pardon me, gentlemen.
I wonder if I might
have a word with you?
They're Klingons,
not kittens.
( suspenseful theme playing )
You will listen!
JANEWAY:
These sensors
show you've placed
holo-emitters
on Decks 5 through 12?
No wonder the system breached.
You've turned Voyager
into one big holodeck.
Can you shut it down?
Yes, but I'm going to have
to initiate an overload.
We'll worry about
making repairs later.
Right now, we've got to put
an end to those simulations.
Janeway to Ensign Kim.
Yes, Captain.
Harry, I'm going
to need your help
overloading
the holo-emitter network.
I'm transferring optical
processor control to you now.
Start charging the
secondary power relays.
We'll use them
to trigger the overload.
I'm on it.
This is going
to take some time.
There are over 800 emitters
that we have to...
Move away from
the controls!
Why haven't you ordered
the cease-fire?
( grunting )
Move away from the controls.
Listen to me.
No!
( grunting )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( grunts )
What are you waiting for?
I am a hunter.
You are my prey.
Run.
( dramatic theme playing )
( crowd yelling )
( gunfire and explosions )
Acknowledged. Out.
Our holographic allies
are losing ground.
The German troops
are surrounding the city.
I don't know how much longer
we can hold them off.
These weapons
are pretty crude.
They're not much help.
Maybe we should
fall back.
Where to? They're coming in
from all sides.
Tuvok, any chance we can get
through that breach
in the hologrid?
Unlikely.
20 more Hirogen
have taken up position
near the opening.
We are outnumbered.
( gunfire continues )
How's it going?
I'm modifying this
explosive device
to emit a photonic burst.
It'll be harmless
to organic tissue,
but it should disrupt
all holographic activity
within 20 meters.
We'll try
to buy you some time.
( martial theme playing )
( panting )
( gasping )
( hatch opening )
( dramatic theme playing )
I'll be in Sickbay.
Schnell!
Ja.
They're closing in.
Seven!
( gunshot )
Surrender.
( groaning )
( breathing heavily )
( grunting )
Auf stehen.
( thunder cracks )
Verdammt.
Bring that one to me.
I will spare
your life for now,
but only because you are
carrying a German child.
( thunder rumbles )
( metallic clanking )
( Janeway gasping )
JANEWAY:
Please don't do this.
I can be of use to you.
I can help you repair the ship.
Don't kill me.
( both grunting )
KAPITAN:
Against the wall.
Your deaths will serve
the glory of the Reich.
Prepare to fire.
( distant yelling )
( dramatic theme playing )
( Klingons yelling fiercely )
( all grunting )
Fight on, warriors!
This way!
Qapla', gentlemen!
Qapla'!
( chambering bullet )
This hunt is over.
Tell your hunters
to stand down.
I'll use this
if you force me to.
( grunting )
( gunshot )
( screaming )
( equipment powering down )
( holograms disappearing )
It's over.
Let's go.
( calm theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 51715.2.
The damage to Voyager
has been extreme.
Both sides
have taken heavy casualties,
and it's clear that no one
is going to win this conflict.
The fighting
has reached a standstill
and the remaining Hirogen
have agreed
to negotiate a truce.
HIROGEN:
What is this?
An optronic datacore.
You can use it to create
holodeck technology
on your own vessels.
I made a promise with your
leader before he died
that I would give this
knowledge to the Hirogen.
Take it.
His ideas were unconventional.
I do not share them.
Was he any more unconventional
than you are...
calling a cease-fire
with your prey?
Only a few days ago,
the thought of speaking
with us on equal terms
would've been inconceivable,
but here we are.
Accept this...
trophy.
You can use it to create
a new future for your people.
At the very least, you can
hang it on your bulkhead.
( sighs )
( majestic theme playing )