( rock theme playing )
( tools clanking )
( clanking )
( blows horn )
What do you think
you're doing, Doc?
An impromptu
auditory exam.
Did I pass?
With flying colors,
which leads me to believe
you did hear me
when I requested
you meet me this morning.
( embarrassed chuckle )
You're right.
I forgot.
I see.
I realize your sick bay
training is purely voluntary,
but you haven't spent any
time there in several weeks
and when I...
try to find you, you're
always in the holodeck.
Correct me if I'm wrong, Doc,
but we haven't been treating
anything more serious
than an ingrown toenail.
That's beside the point.
If an emergency
were to happen,
you must be prepared.
You're too far behind
in your medical texts
to be wasting your time
in the holodeck!
If it's any consolation,
I have spent most
of the morning immersed
in a complicated
surgical procedure.
Really?
A classic case
of atrophied shocks.
They needed to be extracted
to prevent chrome abrasion.
It was touch and
go for a while,
but the prognosis
is excellent.
You'll be ready for
neurosurgery in no time.
Take a look at this, Doc.
This is a fully stock
1969 Chevy Camaro,
one of the earliest
muscle cars ever made.
Imagine, Northern California,
late 20th century.
You're cruising up
Highway 1.
The woofers are pounding.
The wind is whipping
through your hair.
Medieval safety constraints,
internal combustion system,
producing lethal levels
of carbon monoxide.
Hmm. I stand corrected.
This may be just
what you need
to get you back
to Sick Bay.
I should have known
this wouldn't interest you.
It's too much fun.
This isn't about fun, Mr. Paris.
Serving in Sick Bay
is a privilege.
I'd expect you to realize that.
Oh, I do.
I'll be there. Soon.
JANEWAY:
Lieutenant Paris, report
to the Bridge immediately.
( sighs )
I'm on my way.
Somebody call
for a driver?
Take your
station, Tom.
Anything on
scans, Harry?
KIM:
I'm picking up
another spatial distortion
2,000 kilometers away.
CHAKOTAY:
Source?
KIM:
I have no idea.
It looks like
space is folding in on itself.
Shields to full.
It's an alien vessel.
One occupant aboard.
Captain, it looks like
that ship is being powered
by a coaxial warp drive.
Coaxial what?
It's a hypothetical
propulsion system.
Starfleet engineers have been
dreaming about it for years.
In theory, it can literally fold
the fabric of space
allowing a ship
to travel instantaneously
across huge
distances.
The alien warp drive
is overloading.
In theory,
a coaxial drive explosion...
could collapse space
within a radius
of a billion kilometers.
In theory.
Well, let's keep theory
from becoming reality.
Red alert.
( title theme playing )
PARIS:
Scan the vessel.
Can we beam the pilot out?
Too much interference.
The ship's about had it,
Captain.
The coaxial core is breaching.
We should vacate this
area of space at once.
PARIS:
We can't just leave
him like this.
Try one more hail.
Nothing.
Maybe he's ignoring us.
Or maybe he's unconscious. We've
got to do something.
JANEWAY:
Suggestions?
A symmetric warp field.
That should contain
any instabilities
in his space
folding core.
How can you be sure?
Advanced subspace geometry.
It's the one course
at the academy
where I actually paid attention.
We'll tractor him in
to kill his momentum,
and generate a warp field
around his ship.
His flight path is erratic.
We'd be risking
collision.
Captain, I can make this work.
Do it.
Passing through
the residual folds in space.
Steady.
Got him!
TUVOK:
I've extended
our warp field
around his vessel.
His core is powering down.
Nice flying, Tom.
My pleasure.
We're finally receiving a hail.
Open a channel.
Captain Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
Do you need medical attention?
I'm fine, Captain.
Unfortunately,
my ship is not.
If you need to make repairs,
we might be able to help.
That's very generous.
We'll beam you aboard
in a few minutes. Stand by.
STETH:
Thank you.
CAPTAIN:
Tuvok.
Energize.
Welcome.
STETH: Captain.
I know you put yourselves
in danger to rescue me.
I want to thank you.
I'm glad we could help.
I was so eager to
test my new engine,
I pushed it
beyond its limits.
Coaxial warp
doesn't seem to be
the smoothest way
to travel.
It's a violent procedure,
but it allows a ship
to travel through space
at incredible speeds.
Considering the dangers
this method of travel
hardly seems logical.
That's probably true,
but if I were
worrying about danger,
I wouldn't have
become a test pilot.
Where are you from?
The fourth planet
in the Benthan system.
That's about 20 light
years from here.
I'll speak to my engineers
about helping you
with repairs.
Without your coaxial drive,
it's a long way home.
( door beeping )
Come in.
( short exhale )
I'd like to ask
you a favor.
I need a change of pace.
I'd like to help Steth
repair his ship.
This isn't
a good time to ask.
What do you mean?
I've been reading a report
from the doctor.
You didn't show up today.
Well, I was a little
busy this morning...
saving someone's life,
as I recall.
Is there something wrong, Tom?
Anything bothering you?
Nothing is wrong.
Since when is not
wanting to spend
time with the doctor
a capital offense?
You'd have to throw the whole
crew in the brig for that one.
Maybe. I was wondering if
there's something on your mind.
You're showing up
for your duty shifts,
you do what's required,
but your heart doesn't seem
to be in it.
You seem preoccupied.
Like I said,
I think I need a change of pace.
You're a different man
from the one that came
on board four years ago.
You've taken charge of your
life, turned yourself around.
I'd hate to see you ruin it.
I won't.
With your permission,
I'll report to Sick Bay.
Permission denied.
Report to Steth's
ship instead.
Assist in the repairs.
We need our best
man on the job.
And on my way back,
I made the mistake
of flying the prototype
through restricted
Entaban territory.
And?
And, uh...
the Entabans weren't
too pleased to see me.
I limped back to the engineers
on Benthos with phaser holes
through their brand-new
exatanium fuselage.
I think they would
have been happier
to see phaser holes
through me.
( chuckles )
When I was 16, I followed
an ancient human custom.
I took my father's shuttle
out for a joyride,
and proceeded to
fry all the relays.
STETH:
I'm guessing he wasn't happy
about getting it back.
Actually, he didn't.
As far as I know,
it's still at the
bottom of Lake Tahoe.
Here it is.
The coaxial induction drive.
It draws in subatomic particles
and reconfigures
their internal geometries.
And this is what makes
folding space possible?
At least in spurts.
Unfortunately,
particle instabilities
keep overloading my engines,
but I'm gonna to make it work.
I have to keep in motion.
I don't like the
thought of settling down.
Too many new ships to drive,
too many intriguing women.
Yeah. I guess so.
When I get this ship back,
I'm going to be doing
the first test
on a new mithran-class
fighter.
I'm told it's more advanced
than any warship
in the quadrant.
Why don't you
come with me?
We'd have a great time,
you can meet up with
Voyager afterwards.
I-I'd love to do that.
It sounds very exciting...
but I have
responsibilities here,
people who count on me,
and B'Elanna
would be furious.
B'Elanna.
I have to go.
So, you started without me.
I finished without you.
You're a little late.
Uh, sorry.
I was helping Steth
repair his ship.
How's it going?
Um...pretty slow.
We're both stuck on
how to prevent
the particle overloads
in his propulsion system.
Have you tried an isokinetic
containment field?
Yeah. That's the first
thing we tried.
How long do you think these
repairs are going to take?
I don't know.
I was just hoping
that maybe you could help me
recalibrate
the plasma manifolds tonight.
Uh...I, uh...
I probably should
go help Steth.
Tom, is there something wrong?
Why are you interrogating me?
I didn't think I was.
It sounds more like
you want me to account for
every minute that
I'm not with you.
That's ridiculous.
Can't I have some
time to myself?
Can't I do what I want
without having to report
every detail of it to you?
Tom, you can do
whatever you want.
I just wanted to know if
there was something wrong.
I mean lately you've
been canceling dates,
you hide out for hours
in the holodeck...
I am not hiding anything.
That is ridiculous.
Is it?
You haven't even told me
what holodeck program this is
that has you
so fascinated.
( scoffs )
"The Dancing Girls
of Ninipia Prime."
It's very entertaining.
Very funny.
You're overreacting.
I am not overreacting.
There is obviously
something going on,
and you're refusing
to admit it.
Good evening,
Lieutenants.
I see you don't have
dinner yet, Tom.
Can I get you something?
I'm really not hungry.
Excuse me. Are you going
to talk to me about this?
Because if not, I don't want
to sit here anymore.
If you can carry on
an adult conversation
without all
the histrionics...
Good night, Tom.
( sighs )
Computer, run a DNA
stability analysis.
How long before my genome
reverts to its previous form?
COMPUTER:
Time to reversion,
three hours, 13 minutes.
Complete genome recovery
is imminent.
So I was lying
in bed last night
when it hit me.
What you need
is a carburetor.
A carburetor?
Yes. It's a device that's
hundreds of years old.
I can't believe I didn't
think of it yesterday.
Wait. Hundreds
of years old?
Surely that couldn't be
of any use to us now.
It all goes
back to basics.
You would
be surprised
at how often I
find solutions
to 24th century problems
in 20th century technology.
Computer, access
Paris program
alpha one,
"Grease monkey."
( computer beeps )
Grease monkey?
Mechanic lingo.
A car's engine can't
run on pure fuel
so the carburetor
supplies it
with a mixture of
vaporized fuel and air.
And you think we need
a device like that
to dilute the particle stream
as it enters the coaxial drive.
Exactly, and a spare
polaric modulator
from Voyager's impulse drive
should do the trick.
Subatomic dilution!
It never would have
occurred to me.
I think you've solved it.
Well, we can run a few
simulations on the holodeck
before we actually try it.
Oh...I owe you a lot.
You can thank
my lucky toolbox.
It's gotten me out of
hot water more than once.
Mmm.
You're lucky to be stationed
on a ship like this.
Replicators
to feed and clothe you,
holo-technology to
cater to every whim,
hallways filled
with women.
Yeah.
It's great.
You don't sound convinced.
Aren't you
happy here?
Of course I'm happy.
I'm very happy.
I mean...I pilot
one of the most advanced
ships in Starfleet.
I have a beautiful girlfriend.
I'm respected.
I have everything
that I've ever wanted.
You're lucky.
You're part of a family,
part of a structure.
You have rules to guide you.
You don't have to worry about
making a lot of choices.
I usually go
to bed at night
not knowing what the
next day has in store...
what trouble I might get into.
( laughs )
You don't have to
worry about those things.
You're very settled.
I remember those days.
I used to be
a lot like you,
going anywhere...
Doing whatever I wanted.
Making my own rules,
living life my own way.
Well, then there's hope
for me yet.
Maybe someday
I'll settle down too.
But...for now...
I prefer to stay on the move.
( sighs )
Sometimes...I wish
that's what I was doing.
Things'll turn
around for you.
I've always found that
change is inevitable.
It comes when you
least expect it.
( laughs )
Yeah, I suppose.
Now, are we ready
to try this carburetor
idea on my ship?
Just give me five more
minutes to finish up here,
and I'll be right with you.
Five minutes.
And, Tom...
don't dismiss
the suggestion
I made...
about coming with me
to fly the new ship.
It might be fun to escape
the shackles for a while.
Computer, access all files
pertaining
to Lieutenant Tom Paris.
Download into memory core alpha.
COMPUTER:
Please enter
authorization code.
Access granted.
Commencing download.
Hello.
I'm Steth...
a guest of your captain.
I have been apprised
of your presence on Voyager.
You are not authorized
to access the ship's computers.
You must be Seven of Nine.
That is correct.
Tom mentioned you.
He thinks you're
extremely intelligent.
Lieutenant Paris'
opinion of me
is irrelevant to your
being in this room.
Oh, well...Tom felt
we needed some files
for polaric modulators
but he was called away
before we could access them.
I thought I'd find them
myself and help out.
You were mistaken.
He must be present
to download these files.
Oh, I'm about to meet him
at the holodeck.
We can find the files there.
Voyager's hierarchy
is complex.
See that you familiarize
yourself with it.
Good advice.
I'll do that.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
Stardate 51762.4.
The repairs
to Steth's coaxial drive
have been completed
well ahead of schedule.
Everything here looks good.
Just give me one more second
to check the flow field
parameters.
Go ahead.
It's my box wrench.
I've been looking
all over for this.
I know. I should've
asked you, Tom,
but I needed it
for an experiment.
( chuckles )
To, uh...check
your new carburetor?
Not quite.
You're the first humans
I've met and that wrench
had enough cellular residue on
it for me to check your DNA.
I have good news.
( groaning )
We're compatible.
Consider this a favor.
I know how unhappy you've been
with this dreary, settled life,
so I'm taking it off your hands.
I'm betting there's still
some fun to be had here.
Voyager is
a great ship, Tom.
I'll take good care of it.
Sorry I'm late.
We were beginning to wonder
if you were ever coming back.
KIM:
His ship is powering engines.
Something wrong, Tom?
It's nothing.
( sighs )
I'm just really going
to miss that guy.
Mind if I join you?
Not at all...
Commander.
Chakotay will do, Tom.
You don't have to carry this
rules thing too far.
I've been discussing
your engineering report
with the captain.
She was wondering
if we could implement
some of Steth's technology
here on Voyager.
Really?
We thought maybe
you could start on a shuttle.
Do you
think you can do it?
I'm sure I can.
Great. You can start right after
you finish with the doctor.
The doctor?
He needs your help in Sick Bay.
I told him you'd be there.
Of course.
( clearing throat )
Lieutenant.
Hi.
( sighing )
KIM:
I know you've been
avoiding the doctor,
but don't tell me you've
forgotten where Sick Bay is.
( Laughing ):
Oh...not yet.
I was just trying
to figure out
if there's a more
efficient route
between Sick Bay
and my quarters.
I didn't realize you were
that eager to get there.
( chuckling )
So tell me,
are they ready yet?
Uh...not yet.
But they will be soon.
Great. Hey, let me know
if you have any problems.
Polyduranide can be
tough to replicate.
Oh, it sure can be.
I can't wait to get my hands
around one of those clubs.
Ensign Kaplan won't
know what hit her.
What?
We're going to play
golf with her.
We scheduled a
rematch, remember?
Oh, of course.
I can't wait.
Have you been working
on your putting?
You missed both those
two-footers last time.
I won't let it
happen again.
( sighing ):
All right.
Give the doc my best.
I will...
if I ever find him.
You're early,
Mr. Paris.
I see some good came from my
report to Commander Chakotay.
Let's put these extra
few minutes to good use.
Begin with a thorough
bio-bed diagnostic.
I want you to recalibrate
each physiosensor
making sure to enter every
metabolic referent precisely.
Okay.
When you're through there, run
a protein structure analysis,
and then continue your
review of the 37 steps
of a cardiopulmonary
reconstruction procedure.
I'll leave you
to your bio-beds.
( electronic screech )
Did you forget to disengage
the scan emitters?
Sorry.
( electronic screech )
Mr. Paris!
I don't know what's wrong.
I realize
it's complicated,
but you must try again.
Actually,
I'm not feeling so well.
How fortunate you're
already in Sick Bay.
I'll run a few scans.
Uh, no, no, Doc.
That's all right.
To be perfectly
honest with you,
uh...this is so
frustrating for me.
I usually pick things up
a lot faster than this.
You're here to learn,
Mr. Paris.
It will get easier with time.
Well, that's easy
for you to say.
Excuse me?
No offense, Doctor,
but you were programmed
to be a medical genius.
Things always
come easy to you.
Me, I'm just a pilot,
a...grease monkey,
and as hard
as I might try
to become a better
assistant to you,
it's clear to me now
that I'll never be half
the healer that you are.
Do you mean to tell me,
you've been trying
to live up to my standards?
( sighing )
I'm afraid I have.
It all makes sense now.
The misplaced aggression,
the shirking
of responsibilities...
all classic signs of
an inferiority complex.
I had no idea my
superior abilities
were affecting your
psyche so strongly.
Take the rest
of the day off.
Reflect on your strengths.
Realize your worth.
I'll do that, Doctor.
Thank you.
( sighing )
B'Elanna.
What do you think you're doing?
Putting.
In my quarters?
I can't putt in your quarters?
No.
Since when?
( exasperated sigh )
Tom...
what is this?
That is...
a sand wedge.
It's used for getting
out of traps.
Why is it here?
I replicated it for you.
I thought we could play
a little game of golf
on the holodeck before dinner.
So this is your idea...
of an adult conversation?
( exasperated sigh )
I don't know what
you are trying to accomplish
with this little stunt,
but let me assure you,
it is not working.
I am sorry if you are bored
because Steth is gone,
but that doesn't mean
that you can just walk in here,
and pretend like you
haven't been shutting me out.
You're being a little hard
on Steth.
If it wasn't for him,
I wouldn't be here right now.
Really?
I mentioned to him that we were
having some problems,
and he urged me to...
come and talk to you,
to try to work things out,
to admit I was wrong.
I made a mistake, B'Elanna,
and I'm sorry.
I won't shut
you out anymore.
In fact, I went to
the doctor and begged
to be excused
from my duties.
I realize it's only
a few extra hours,
but they're hours I
wanna spend with you.
Steth...turned out to be
a positive influence on you.
( groaning )
Computer, where...
com-computer, where are we?
COMPUTER:
Navigation Mmatrix 171,
the Kotaba expanse.
Coaxial leap complete.
How far are we from Voyager?
( sighing )
Computer, lock in Voyager's
last known coordinates,
and activate
differential induction drive.
COMPUTER:
Unable to execute command.
Why not?
COMPUTER:
The differential induction
drive has been secured.
A security access code is
required for coaxial leap.
AVIK:
This is Commander Avik
of the Benthan Guard.
We're taking you into custody.
Prepare to surrender the vessel
to us at once.
Benthan? I need a second
to explain, Commander.
I'm not who you think--
AVIK:
We do not negotiate
with thieves.
No...you don't understand!
I-I need this ship
to get back to Voyager.
AVIK:
Surrender the vessel peacefully
or we will use force.
Why is everybody trying
to shoot me today?
You know what I'm here for.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Who are you?
I'm Steth.
What?
Look at me.
You did wear this body
for nearly a year,
before you switched
it with mine.
That's my body you're in now.
I want it back.
Bear with me
for...for a second.
We have more
in common than you might think.
This better be good, Tom.
I left Vorik right
in the middle
of an E.P.S.
Recalibration.
( sighs ):
You can thank me later.
So what's my big surprise?
What would you say...
to 24 glorious hours
on the famed fourth planet
of the Kendren System?
You mean the planet where Neelix
is gathering food samples?
Mm-hmm. I ran a few scans and
found the most incredible beach
on one
of the smaller continents.
I replicated
a picnic lunch for us.
Voyager isn't leaving orbit
until tomorrow.
We'd have an entire day.
( laughs )
Only a day?
Oh, I think that we would
need at least a week.
Oh, I wish we could,
but we've only got a day.
You're serious, aren't you?
Completely.
Do you know how much
trouble we would be in?
What could Janeway
do, execute us?
Tom, I am swamped.
I can't get away for
an hour, let alone 24.
B'Elanna...
I have responsibilities here.
We both do.
Responsibilities?
I don't care!
Tom, you're hurting me.
You're a real
disappointment to me.
Do you know that?
I don't know what
I ever saw in you.
( sighs )
Seven.
What brings you
here at this hour?
We were supposed to meet in
the shuttle bay at 2100 hours.
Did you forget?
I did.
I got so caught up
with my reading,
I guess it slipped my mind.
Sorry.
The capillaries in your eyes
are swollen, Lieutenant,
and I see signs of vascular
congestion in your cheeks.
Are you intoxicated?
No, not at all.
I was just exploring
the replicator,
trying some alien beverages.
Only a few were alcoholic.
You are not officially off duty
for another 78 minutes.
I'm on break.
Would you like to join me?
I could replicate another
trakian ale for you.
That will not be necessary.
Oh, relax, Seven.
You're not on the
borg cube anymore.
We could finish our work
on the shuttle tomorrow.
That would be an
inefficient use of our time.
I will complete
the work myself.
( sighs )
Fine.
Before I leave,
I would like to know
why you were reading the
captain's personal logs.
I wasn't.
I saw the pad.
It was unmistakably
the captain's logs.
You're wrong.
You're...confused.
You couldn't possibly
have seen anything.
You know I possess
an eidetic memory.
I require only seconds
to commit what I see to memory.
Would you like me to quote
the passage you were reading?
I'm warning you,
stay out of my way.
Don't interfere in things
that don't concern you.
If you bother me again,
I will make things very
unpleasant for you.
Remove your hand from my arm.
Don't be foolish.
You'll regret it.
( door beeping )
Enter.
You wanted to see me, Captain.
Yes.
I received a rather disturbing
report from Seven of Nine
regarding
your conduct last night.
She claims you were
drinking on duty.
( scoffs )
She's mistaken, Captain.
Don't lie
to me, Tom.
I checked the computers.
You replicated
five alcoholic beverages
in the mess hall.
She also said
you threatened her.
( sighs )
I'm sorry, Captain.
B'Elanna and I had an argument.
I was upset.
And is that why you were reading
my personal logs?
I wasn't.
Seven recited a passage I'd
written word for word.
She probably accessed
those files herself.
Captain, you can't take
the word of a borg over mine.
This has to stop, Tom.
Your conduct lately
has been bizarre,
and I've heard far
too many complaints
from far too many
people to dismiss it.
Chakotay, the doctor,
Seven of Nine.
They're all worried
about you, and so am I.
You're right, Captain.
I need some rest.
I'll go right to my quarters.
Tom...
as your captain
and as your friend...
I want you to report to
Sick Bay for some tests.
We have to find out
if there's
something physical
that's causing
this behavior.
This is crazy.
I don't need any help.
It's an order.
JANEWAY:
Security, I need you
in the ready room now!
( coughing )
Are you hurt, Captain?
No. Take him
to Sick Bay.
Keep security with him.
( coughing )
The coaxial drive will be
online in a few minutes.
Good. I've just about overridden
all the lockout commands.
No offense, but I'd like
to get out of your body
as soon as possible.
The alien seems capable
of some sort of
selective DNA exchange.
He absorbs new DNA
while depositing his
current genetic material
into his victims.
Let's hope he can
reverse that process.
That's the last
lockout command.
We're set for
coaxial warp.
Let's find Voyager.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
The doctor has treated
Mr. Paris' phaser wounds
but has been unable to
wake him.
The motive for his attack
remains a mystery.
Neurological scans
yielded very little,
but I did find something
very interesting
in his blood analysis.
There are traces of
a second DNA pattern
in his nucleotide structure.
Possibly the result
of a genetic virus.
Could this be the cause
of his recent behavior?
I don't know, but
I'm running more scans
to see how this
might have affected
his neurological
functions.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain, a vessel just emerged
from coaxial space
off our starboard bow.
Keep me informed, Doctor.
Hail them.
STETH:
Captain Janeway.
Oh, welcome back,
Mr. Steth.
I know this sounds crazy,
Captain, but I'm not Steth.
I'm Tom Paris.
I beg your pardon?
We're dealing with an alien
who's an identity thief.
He traded places with me.
Please beam us aboard.
Maintain your position
while we consider your request.
End transmission.
Hold him in a tractor beam
until you hear from me.
I have a feeling Steth
and his new friend
are behind whatever's
happened to Tom.
Captain?
No time to explain.
I'll be in Sick Bay.
( clattering )
Captain?
Commander, I'm reading
an unauthorized shuttle launch.
It's the captain.
She's in the shuttle
Tom's been working on.
Try hailing her.
She's not
responding.
Hail Steth's ship.
Look, I don't
know who you are,
but I want to know
what's happening here.
Who's on that shuttle?
Captain Janeway.
No. I'm betting the alien
switched my body...
Tom's body for hers.
You've got to let us out
of this tractor beam.
We can catch her
with this ship.
Chakotay...it's me.
How do I know that?
The other day in your office,
you told me
I'd turned my life around.
Well, give me the chance
to prove it.
Let me go after the shuttle.
It is the only way
we can get everybody
back into the right body.
Harry...
disengage the tractor beam.
Twenty thousand
kilometers and closing.
Has he detected us yet?
I'd say he has.
Gentlemen, I'd advise you
to reconsider this pursuit.
Killing me will only keep you
trapped in those bodies.
He's right.
We can't risk killing him.
Yeah, but nothing's keeping
him from killing us.
Damn! The ship's not nearly
as maneuverable as a shuttle.
Shields are down.
I'm surprised you're so eager
to reclaim your life
on Voyager, Tom.
I was just as disappointed
with it as you were.
Then I guess we were both wrong.
It's time to move on again.
Oh, Tom...be sure to send
my best regards to B'Elanna.
Hmm?
( chuckling )
He's charging
the coaxial drive.
Set the sensors to track him.
I can't. He's blocking us.
We won't be able to follow him
once he goes
into coaxial warp.
We're losing him!
The carburetor!
We added
a polaric modulator
to the coaxial drive.
If I can target
the modulator,
hit it with a
chromo electric pulse,
that'll disrupt
his engines.
Here goes.
( alarm blaring )
( engines revving )
PARIS:
I hope you still have
my box wrench.
Faulty carburetors
can be a pain to fix.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
Stardate 51775.2.
While the alien intruder
remains trapped in the body
of his last victim,
the doctor has found a way
to return Tom, Steth and me
to our own bodies.
Doctor,
I can't thank you enough.
You've given me my life back.
DOCTOR:
All in a day's work.
There were times
when I thought
I would be stuck
in that body forever.
And believe me
I'm just as happy to be back
to the old Tom Paris.
What do you
plan to do now?
I'm going to take
her back to Bentha.
I hope to find
the person
who belongs
to that body.
But who knows
if that's the end of it?
We have no idea
how long she or he
has been switching
identities.
It may take a while...
but I will do
whatever I can
to find everyone
you've violated.
A security team will
escort her to your ship,
and erect a force field
to contain her.
( rock theme playing )
So this is where
you've been hiding?
A garage?
It's more than
just a garage.
This is a monument
to hundreds and
hundreds of hours...
that I probably should
have spent with you.
Probably?
Definitely.
It's a lovely garage, Tom,
but I still don't understand
why you brought me here.
Well, consider it
a symbolic gesture.
It's my less than subtle attempt
to...let you in.
I see.
To make it clear, that I mean
almost as much to you as a...
a Cam-a-ro.
It's a mint condition,
1969...
Ca-mare-oh.
And yes...you mean
a lot more to me.
( title theme playing )