COMPUTER:
0600 hours.
Regeneration cycle complete.
Daily log, Seven of Nine,
Stardate 15781.2.
Today, Ensign Kim and I
will conduct
a comprehensive diagnostic
of the aft sensor array.
I have allocated three hours,
20 minutes for the task,
and an additional 17 minutes
for Ensign Kim's usual
conversational digressions.
I am scheduled to take
a nutritional supplement
at 1500 hours, engage in one
hour of cardiovascular activity.
Then, I intend to review a text
the doctor recommended entitled,
A Christmas Carol.
He believes it will have
educational value.
End log.
I'll get this.
Don't give me
any hints.
I have no intention
of doing so.
Ensign.
Hi, Seven.
Are you ready to begin
our sensor diagnostic?
Is it 0600 already?
We've been playing
all night.
Vulcan Kal-Toh.
For a game of logic,
you'd be surprised at
how addictive it is.
Give me a few more minutes
to figure this out.
You should attend
to your duties, Ensign.
I'll accept
your forfeit.
No way.
This is the closest
I've ever come to beating you,
and I'm not giving up now.
Impressive.
Elementary
spatial harmonics.
Are you ready now?
Yeah. Sure.
I would have
gotten that.
Is there anything
you don't know?
I was Borg.
"I was Borg."
That's what you always say.
But what does it mean?
You have the knowledge
of 10,000 species in your head?
Not exactly.
Each drone's experiences
are processed by the collective.
Only useful information
is retained.
Still, that
probably makes you
the most intelligent
human being alive.
Probably.
So what do you need
the rest of us for?
Forget I asked.
What was that?
We just dropped out of warp.
CHAKOTAY:
What's the problem?
We were hit
by some kind of shock wave.
Source?
Checking.
Hold on.
I just lost all
my sensor readings.
The computer is bringing up
some kind of message,
but I can't access it.
You'd better take a
look at this.
I can see it.
What is it?
I have no idea.
My command codes aren't working.
The computer says
I have insufficient clearance
to access the message.
We can't function like this.
I'm going to get Harry up here
to trace the source.
Don't do anything.
I'll take care of this.
Send all sensor data about the
particle wave to my ready room.
Tom, disengage engines
and hold position here.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain...
what's going on?
I can't explain right now.
Don't discuss any of this
with the rest of the crew.
I'll have further instructions
for you soon.
( title theme playing )
Computer, seal the doors
to this room.
No entry
without my authorization.
COMPUTER:
Doors are sealed.
Access secured data file
Omega One.
COMPUTER:
Voiceprint confirmed.
State clearance code.
Janeway-1153-red,
Clearance Level Ten.
Confirmed.
Sensors have detected
the Omega phenomenon
within 1.2 lightyears
of this vessel.
Implement the Omega Directive
immediately.
( Sighing )
All other priorities
have been rescinded.
Display sensor data.
I've been informed this
is a highly classified mission.
Information will be provided on
a need-to-know basis,
Captain's orders.
Classified? By who?
We're 60,000 light years
from Starfleet.
Like I said,
need-to-know.
B'Elanna, she wants
you to install
multiphasic shielding
around the warp core.
I've never seen this shield
configuration.
I'd like to run a couple
of computer simulations
to make sure
it's stable.
No time.
She needs this
done by 1100 hours.
1100? I don't think
that's possible.
Make it possible.
Are we attempting to
protect the core
from some form
of subspace radiation?
I don't know
any more than you do.
It will be difficult to complete
the task without more data.
The data you've got
will have to do.
Tom, start modifying
a shuttlecraft to withstand
extreme thermal stress,
12,000 kelvins at least.
Aye, Sir.
Does all this have
anything to to do with
that secret message that
the captain received?
What have you heard?
Rumors, mostly.
Janeway's been locked
in her ready room
for the last 16 hours.
Something about
an Omega Directive.
Omega?
Ring a bell?
Look, the speculation
ends right here.
Now, I expect you
to carry out your assignments
with a minimum of gossip,
understood?
I know it's hard
not to wonder.
Frankly, I'm
curious myself,
but the Captain was
very adamant about this.
Get going.
The Captain
wants to see you.
I thought she might.
( door beeping )
Come in.
What do you know about
the Omega Directive?
Everything you do,
most likely.
I thought as much.
If the Borg assimilated
Starfleet Captains,
you would possess
all of their knowledge.
That's correct.
Do you intend to
carry out the directive?
Yes.
Then sensors have
detected the molecule.
So it would appear,
but we have to confirm it.
"We"?
You're going to help me
carry out the directive.
Protocol forbids me
from discussing this mission
with any of my crew,
but since you already
know about it,
my choice is to
either work with you,
or...confine you
to quarters.
Perhaps you should
do the latter.
I will not help
you destroy Omega.
It should be harnessed.
That's impossible.
The Borg believe
otherwise.
Explain.
On one occasion
we were able to
create a single
Omega molecule.
We kept it stable
for one-trillionth
of a nanosecond
before it destabilized.
We didn't have enough
boronite ore left
to synthesize more,
but the knowledge
we gained
allowed us to...
refine our theories.
The Borg have
been waiting
for the chance
to test them out.
Yes.
But we never found
another source of the ore...
until now.
Sorry...
but if someone
out there is
experimenting
with Omega
I'm under orders
to stop them.
Otherwise, this entire
Quadrant would be at risk.
Those orders are the result of
Starfleet's ignorance and fear.
I can alleviate your ignorance.
As for your fear--
sometimes fear should be
respected, Seven. Tell me...
how many Borg were sacrificed
during this experiment?
Twenty nine vessels, 600,000
drones, but that is irrelevant.
Not to me, not to my crew,
and not to the people
who live in this Quadrant.
I'm going to neutralize
this threat, Seven,
with or without
your help.
I will assist you.
You will?
I have waited many years
to observe this
molecule firsthand.
I will not deny myself
that experience.
All right.
Go back to your cargo bay.
Assemble all the data
you have about Omega.
I'll expect a report
within the hour.
I didn't realize you had
such a strong
scientific curiosity.
Not curiosity...
desire.
Desire?
Omega is infinitely complex,
yet harmonious.
To the Borg
it represents perfection.
I wish to understand
that perfection.
The Borg's Holy Grail.
Captain?
Never mind.
I'll see you in an hour.
Arithrazine? What for?
I'm going
on an away mission.
What are you
planning to do,
stroll through
a supernova?
Something like that...
20 milligrams,
when can you
have it ready?
Captain, arithrazine is used
for the most severe cases
of theta radiation poisoning.
A physician must be present
to monitor the treatment.
That won't be possible.
Then I'm afraid
I can't accommodate you.
I'd be in violation
of Starfleet medical protocols.
Well, I'm overriding
those protocols.
Don't tell me,
"The Omega Directive",
Whatever that might be.
The arithrazine, Doctor.
It'll be ready in the morning.
Have it sent to
the shuttle bay.
Captain, I don't know what's
going on here, but I'd hate
this to be the last time
I ever see you.
Please be careful.
I will.
( beeping )
SEVEN OF NINE:
I've analyzed the sensor logs
using Borg algorithms.
The shock wave we detected
indicates not one,
but possibly hundreds
of Omega molecules.
Location?
Within ten lightyears.
I'm having difficulty
isolating the
exact star system.
Hundreds of molecules.
That changes everything.
A shuttle mission
may be insufficient.
We require the resources of this
entire crew.
We're going to need
more firepower,
more protection.
Transfer your data
to the astrometrics lab.
I'll work on it there.
TUVOK:
Calibration complete.
Phase modulator.
Detonator circuits?
On standby.
We're ready to load
the gravimetric charge.
This looks like enough
for a 50-isoton explosion.
Fifty four, to be exact.
What are we planning to do,
blow up a small planet?
I don't know.
This warhead isn't
standard issue.
Who designed it, the Captain?
JANEWAY:
Mr. Kim, you ask too
many questions.
Change of plans, gentlemen.
Increase the charge
to 80 isotons.
Aye, Captain.
Harry, when you're done here,
give B'Elanna a hand
with the shuttlecraft.
She's reinforcing the hull.
Right.
Ensign Hickman thinks
it's species 8472.
Pardon me?
That's his theory.
There's an opening
in fluidic space,
and Captain Janeway
has to shut it down.
Want to know what I think?
No.
I think there's a type-six
protostar out there,
and the Captain's planning
on detonating it,
and opening up a wormhole
to the Alpha Quadrant.
In theory,
it's possible.
And because she doesn't want
to get her hopes up,
she's not telling anybody.
Then I wouldn't suggest
getting your hopes up.
Then what do you think it is?
I do not engage in
idle speculation.
Oh, come on, Tuvok.
Aren't you curious?
Yes, but we have a task at hand.
The phase modulator.
( door beeping )
Come in.
Status report.
Everything's going
according to schedule.
Good.
The Omega directive doesn't
allow me to say much,
but I want you to
know what to expect.
At 0600 hours,
I'll be leaving
in a shuttle with
Seven of Nine.
Would it be out of line
to ask where you're going?
I can tell you this,
one of two things
is going to happen.
Either Seven and I will
succeed on our mission,
and return within
a few days,
or your long-range
sensors will detect
a large explosion
in subspace.
If that occurs, you'll have
less than ten seconds to jump
to warp and get the
hell out of here.
Head for the
alpha quadrant,
and don't look
back. Understood?
I always thought that
Starfleet was run by
duty-crazed bureaucrats,
but I find it hard to believe
that even they
would order a Captain
to go on a suicide mission.
This shuttle excursion
is your idea, isn't it?
Let's just say
I've had to...
amend the Directive
given the circumstances.
But you have your orders
and I expect you to follow them.
That's expecting a lot.
You're asking me to abandon
my Captain and closest friend,
without even telling me why.
If it were a simple
matter of trust,
I wouldn't hesitate to
tell you...
but we've encountered situations
where information was
taken from us by force.
I can't allow knowledge of Omega
to go beyond Voyager.
That's a reasonable argument,
but you're not always
a reasonable woman.
You're determined
to protect this crew,
and this time you've
taken it too far.
A dangerous mission,
fine, I'll acknowledge that,
but isn't it more
likely to succeed
with everyone behind you,
working together?
Ordinarily, I'd agree,
but this Directive was issued
many years ago.
Starfleet didn't exactly have
our predicament in mind, did it?
Lost in the Delta Quadrant
with no backup.
I can't ignore the orders,
but I won't ask the crew
to risk their lives
because of my obligation.
My obligation.
That's where you're wrong.
Voyager may be alone out here,
but you're not.
Let us help you.
We'll keep
classified information
limited to the senior staff.
We'll take
every security precaution.
Just don't try to do this alone.
Assemble the troops.
If we were in the
Alpha Quadrant right now,
we wouldn't be having
this conversation.
I'd be in contact
with Starfleet Command,
and they'd send in
a specialized team
to deal with the crisis.
In their absence, we're
going to have to make do
with the training
I've received,
and the knowledge Seven of Nine
has retained from the Borg.
You've all seen
this symbol.
Omega...the last letter
of the Greek alphabet,
chosen by Starfleet to
represent a threat
not only to the federation,
but to the entire galaxy.
Only Starship Captains
and Federation Flag Officers
have been briefed
on the nature of this threat.
What you're about to hear
will not go beyond these
bulkheads. Is that clear?
Good.
This is Omega.
A molecule?
Not just any molecule...
the most powerful substance
known to exist.
A single Omega molecule
contains the same energy
as a warp core.
In theory, a small chain of them
could sustain a civilization.
The molecule was
first synthesized
over a hundred years ago
by a Starfleet physicist
named Ketteract.
I think he was hoping to develop
an inexhaustible power source.
Or a weapon.
Ketteract managed to synthesize
a single molecule
particle of Omega.
But it only existed
for a fraction of a second
before it destabilized.
This was a classified research
center in the Lantaru sector.
Ketteract and 126
of the federation's
leading scientists were
lost in the accident.
Rescue teams
attempting to reach the site
discovered an unexpected
secondary effect.
There were
subspace ruptures
extending out
several lightyears.
The Lantaru sector...
it's impossible to create
a stable warp field there.
You can only fly through
it at sublight speeds.
I was always told that
it was a natural phenomenon.
You're saying it was caused by
a single molecule of this stuff?
Omega destroys subspace.
A chain reaction
involving a handful of molecules
could devastate subspace
throughout an entire quadrant.
If that were to happen...
warp travel would
become impossible.
Space-faring civilization
as we know it
would cease to exist.
When Starfleet realized
Omega's power,
they suppressed
all knowledge of it.
DOCTOR:
Have you detected
Omega here,
in the Delta Quadrant?
I'm afraid so.
I've been authorized
to use whatever means
necessary to destroy it.
Tom, I've calculated
the location of the molecules.
I'll transfer the coordinates
to the helm.
Take us there at full impulse.
Aye, Captain.
I don't have to tell you
what's at stake.
If a large-scale
Omega explosion occurs,
we will lose the ability
to go to warp forever.
We've got our work
cut out for us.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
Encrypt log entry.
We're approaching
the star system
where we believe
we'll find Omega.
I have to admit,
I've never been
this apprehensive
about a mission.
I know how Einstein must have
felt about the atom bomb,
or Marcus when she developed
the Genesis Device.
They watched helplessly
as science took
a destructive course.
But I have the chance
to prevent that from happening.
I just hope it's not too late.
Status report?
This is a harmonic
resonance chamber.
The Borg designed it to contain
and stabilize Omega.
I thought I asked you to
work on the photon torpedo.
The torpedo
may be insufficient.
I can modify this chamber
to emit an inverse frequency.
It will be enough to dissolve
Omega's interatomic bonds.
Here's to Borg ingenuity.
This is excellent
work, Seven.
We may need this.
The modifications require
several complex calculations.
Assist me.
I guess I will.
I'm curious...
when did the Borg
discover Omega?
Two hundred
twenty nine years ago.
Assimilation?
Yes.
Of 13 different species.
Thirteen?
It began with species 262.
They were primitive,
but their oral history
referred to
a powerful substance
which could burn the sky.
And the Borg were intrigued...
which led them to species 263.
They too, were primitive,
and believed it was a drop
of blood from their creator.
Fascinating!
Yes, but irrelevant.
We followed this trail of myth
for many years,
until finally
assimilating a species
with useful scientific data.
We then created
the molecule ourselves.
Omega caused quite a stir among
my own species.
Federation cosmologists
had a theory...
that the molecule
once existed in nature...
for an infinitesimal
period of time
at the exact moment
of the Big Bang.
Some claimed Omega
was the primal source of energy
for the explosion
that began our universe.
A creation myth, like any other.
Perhaps.
What is it the Borg say?
That Omega is perfect?
Yes.
Is that a theory or a belief?
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Captain.
Go ahead.
We're approaching
the coordinates.
I'm on my way.
I'm leaving this project
in your hands.
Use whatever resources
and personnel you need.
Understood.
We've entered a
planetary system.
Inhabited?
There's a pre-warp
civilization
on the outermost planet.
The source of Omega
seems to be further in.
The damage to subspace
in this region is extreme.
We won't be able
to go to warp.
We are encountering distortions.
Track their origin.
An M-class moon.
We're in visual range.
On screen.
TUVOK:
There is a subnucleonic reaction
occurring in the upper
atmosphere,
it is apparently
emanating from a structure
on the moon's surface.
Can your sensors
penetrate the atmosphere?
PARIS: Stand by.
My God.
Over 300,000 square
kilometers...destroyed.
Scan the structure.
Are there any
Omega molecules remaining?
I can't tell.
Several sections of the outpost
are still shielded.
I'm detecting life signs.
How many?
A few dozen, maybe. It's hard
to get a clear reading.
Harry, can we transport
to the surface?
I can get you there...
but conditions in the structure
aren't good,
there are high levels
of radiation.
Tuvok...
assemble a rescue team,
and have them report to Sick Bay
for arithrazine inoculations.
Tell the Doctor to
prepare for casualties.
Tom, move Voyager
into a high orbit,
and then join
the away team.
We'll need a field medic.
Yes, Ma'am.
You're going with them?
If Omega's still down there,
I have to find it.
I'll keep an open comlink
with the ship.
You have the bridge.
JANEWAY:
I'm picking up
Omega's resonance frequency.
It's here,
but I can't pinpoint a location.
I need to ask you questions
about the experiments
you've been conducting here.
There was...an accident.
We lost containment.
The substance you were
trying to create,
did any of it survive
the explosion?
Yes.
Where?
Inside the primary
test chamber.
Who are you?
Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
We're here to help you.
Away team to Voyager, two to
beam directly to Sick Bay.
CHAKOTAY:
Aye, Captain.
This door is solid duritanium,
13 centimeters thick.
Can we get it open?
The duritanium has melted
into the door frame.
We will need to cut
through the metal with phasers.
Do it.
Captain...
I'd be negligent
if I didn't point out
that we are about to violate
the Prime Directive.
For the duration of this mission
the Prime Directive
is rescinded.
Let's get this over with.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Crewman Dell,
I'm assigning you a task
more suited
to your abilities.
Calibrate the ionic-pressure
seals on the observation ports.
Your new designation
is Three of Ten.
Yes, Ma'am.
I've got more isolinear
processors for you to install.
Thanks, but I need to get the
power relays online first.
Are you sure
that's a good idea?
Ensign Wildman
was assigned to that.
This is ridiculous.
I'm not going to waste time
just because Seven
wants to turn this team
into her own
private collective.
She says
it's more efficient.
Maybe for a
bunch of drones.
Six of Ten, this is not your
assignment.
Please, stop
calling me that.
You are compromising
our productivity.
I am reassigning you
to chamber maintenance.
Your new designation
is Two of Ten.
( laughing )
Wait a minute.
You're demoting me?
Since when do the Borg
pull rank?
A Starfleet protocol I adapted.
I find it most useful.
I'm glad you're not the Captain.
How's it coming?
SEVEN OF NINE:
The crew can be
quite efficient
when properly organized.
The harmonic chamber will be
completed within the hour.
Good, I'll let the Captain know.
Has she retrieved any new data
from the surface?
Not yet. They're still trying to
access the primary test chamber.
Were there survivors?
A few.
The Doctor's treating them
in Sick Bay.
Commander...
Seven's taking this
"Hive mentality"
Just a little too far.
Designated functions,
numbered drones...
I wouldn't be surprised
if she started plugging
us into alcoves.
When in the collective,
Harry...adapt.
Which of them is the
senior researcher?
This gentleman.
Why do you ask?
He has knowledge I require.
He also happens to be
barely conscious.
Come back in an hour.
Unacceptable.
Unavoidable.
This is my Sick Bay.
The man needs to recover.
The captain left me in charge
of our efforts on Voyager.
I would be negligent
if I ignored a new
source of information.
( sighs )
Our next social skills
seminar is entitled,
"Adding diplomatic flair
to future negotiations."
How are you feeling, Sir?
Better, thank you.
Are you comfortable enough
to speak with this individual?
Keep it brief.
How many of the molecules were
you able to synthesize?
Two hundred million?
I'm not certain.
What is the iso-frequency
of your containment field?
1.68 terrahertz.
We used the molecules
on resonance
to calculate the field.
That should've been enough
to stabilize them.
( scoffs )
Obviously it wasn't.
Obviously.
But your approach is innovative.
Perhaps I can adapt your
technique and improve upon it.
You will assist me.
Our equipment was destroyed.
If you can transfer the
molecules to your ship...
maybe they can be saved.
I have no intention of
saving them.
What?
My orders are to destroy
the Omega molecules.
This is my life's work...
the salvation of my people.
Will you assist me or not?
Our resources are nearly gone.
The future of my people
depends on this discovery.
Then your answer is no.
Small-minded creatures!
You destroy whatever
you don't understand!
Rescue ships are on the way.
They won't let you do it.
Please, try to be calm.
Seven, you'll
have to leave.
You don't realize
what you're doing.
You don't know what this is...
what this means.
On the contrary...
I understand perfectly.
We've disabled
the locking mechanism.
Narrow your phaser beams to
cut through the inner seal.
Inadvisable.
We'd risk penetrating
the containment field.
Then we'll have to use
some elbow grease.
Give me a hand.
Oh.
Right.
There's enough here
to wipe out subspace
across half the Quadrant.
I'll order the away
teams back to Voyager,
and target this facility
with the gravimetric charge.
It won't be enough.
We'll have to go
with our Borg option.
Ensign.
ENSIGN:
Yes, Captain.
Return to the ship.
Tell Commander Chakotay
to help Seven complete
the harmonic chamber.
We'll have to transport Omega
directly to the ship.
That means finding a way
to shut down
this containment field.
It's unfortunate we
can't study this
phenomenon
in more detail.
We may not have the
opportunity again.
Let's hope we never do.
A curious statement
from a woman of science.
I'm also a woman who
occasionally knows when to quit.
Take another look
at your tricorder.
Omega's too dangerous.
I won't risk half the quadrant
to satisfy our curiosity.
It's arrogant
and it's irresponsible.
The final frontier
has some boundaries
that shouldn't be crossed...
and we're looking at one.
We don't need to destroy
the molecules.
I believe I've found a way
to stabilize them.
The alien in sick bay calibrated
his containment field
using Omega's own resonance,
an approach unknown
to the Borg.
I've modified
the chamber...
Those weren't
your orders.
The Captain wants
Omega eliminated.
That is still an option
if she insists on
yielding to her fear.
Show me what you've done.
This simulation
shows the molecules
in their free state,
highly unstable.
I've modified the chamber
to emit a harmonic wave form
that will dampen
the molecules.
Looks great in theory,
but this is only a simulation.
How are you going to test it?
On Omega.
( scoffs ): Bad idea.
One mistake,
and no one will be around
for a second try.
It will work.
Someday, maybe.
Hang on to your research.
For now, we stick to the plan.
Stand by to transport the
molecules into this chamber,
and neutralize them as ordered.
I have been a member
of this crew for nine months.
In all of that time
I have never made
a personal request.
I am making one now.
Allow me to proceed...
please.
Why is this so important to you?
( sighs )
Particle zero-one-zero...
the Borg designation
for what you call Omega.
Every drone is aware
of its existence.
We were instructed
to assimilate it at all costs.
It is...perfection.
The molecules exist
in a flawless state.
Infinite parts
functioning as one.
Like the Borg.
Precisely.
I am no longer Borg,
but I still need to understand
that perfection.
Without it, my existence
will never be complete.
Commander,
you are a spiritual man.
That's right.
If you had the chance to see
your God,
your great spirit...
what would you do?
I'd pursue it...
with all my heart.
Then you understand.
I think I do.
I'll inform the Captain
of your discovery.
For now, her orders stand.
Thank you.
( mellow theme playing )
Set the confinement beam
to its narrowest dispersion.
Understood.
Then we'll target this facility
with the gravimetric torpedo.
If anything goes wrong
during transport,
that'll be our only hope.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Janeway.
We've detected two ships
on an intercept course.
They're not responding
to hails.
How long until they get here?
Less than
four minutes, Captain.
JANEWAY:
Stand by to transport
the molecules directly
to the harmonic chamber.
Understood. Bridge to Cargo Bay.
Yes, Commander.
CHAKOTAY:
Seven, get ready.
We'll have to do this quickly.
That's not advisable.
We don't have a choice.
The alien ships are
on their way.
Then I recommend moving the ship
within 5,000 kilometers
of the surface.
PARIS:
That'll take us right
into the atmosphere.
With our shields down,
we won't be able to withstand
the thermal reaction
for more than a few seconds.
Then we'll only get
one shot at this.
Take us in.
Aye, Sir.
Transporter status?
Targeting scanners are locked.
Captain, are you ready?
Pattern enhancers
are active.
Do it.
We're 11,000 kilometers
from the surface.
If we get much closer,
we'll incinerate.
We're losing structural
integrity.
PARIS:
Nine thousand kilometers.
We're close enough.
Energize.
Initiating transport.
The Omega molecules are stable.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Transport was successful.
I've got the away team
in Transporter Room 2.
Get us out of here,
maximum impulse.
Already on it.
How far are away are
those ships?
They're right on our tail.
CHAKOTAY:
We're heading into
an area of open space,
no indications of life
or any kind of technology.
We can carry out
the procedure
with no risk
to anyone else.
Except those two ships
behind us.
Can we stay ahead of them?
Not for long.
When can we clear the subspace
ruptures and go to warp?
Ten, maybe 15 minutes?
But those ships will
catch up to us before then.
Well, we have one advantage.
We've got Omega.
They won't risk
firing at us...
at least not until
they've run out of options.
That should give us a chance
to neutralize the molecules.
Captain, we might have
another problem.
Seven of Nine?
She's convinced she
can stabilize Omega.
I thought we'd
settled that question.
While you were on the surface,
she showed me a pretty
convincing simulation
of how it could be done.
I should've known she
wouldn't just let this go.
I'll be in Cargo Bay 2.
Seven, the procedure?
It's working.
Eleven percent of the molecules
have already been neutralized.
Let's see if we can
speed up the process a little.
Did commander Chakotay
tell you about my idea?
Yes.
Then you will allow me
to stabilize the
remaining molecules?
You know I can't do that.
Your Starfleet Directive is
no longer relevant,
I have found a way
to control Omega.
I don't care if you can
make it sing and dance,
we're getting rid of it.
A foolish decision.
Yes, but it's mine to make.
Now, step aside.
I could have done this
without your permission,
but I chose to follow
your command structure.
I should've made the attempt.
I still can.
But you won't.
You know I'm not
trying to stop you
from finding perfection...
but I can't risk the
safety of this Quadrant.
Omega must end here.
We both know that.
Status?
Eighteen percent.
This could take hours.
Can you increase the
harmonic resonance?
Yes, but it would
rupture the chamber.
How many molecules would we
neutralize?
Forty, 50 percent
at best.
That's good enough.
Our torpedo can take
care of the rest.
Janeway to Bridge.
CHAKOTAY:
Chakotay here.
Chakotay, I want you
to clear Deck 4,
and put emergency forcefields
around this section.
Prepare to decompress
Cargo Bay 2 on my command.
Understood.
Tuvok,
load the gravimetric torpedo.
Once we've jettisoned
the chamber...fire.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
Harmonic resonance
to maximum.
Commander, they're
closing on us.
They're attempting to stop us
with a tractor beam.
Adjust shields to compensate.
They're hailing us.
On screen.
Disengage your engines,
and prepare to be boarded.
I can't do that.
You've stolen our technology,
abducted our people.
Your people are safe. They're
receiving medical care.
I'll be glad to get them
back to you when this is over,
but we're keeping the molecules.
I won't allow this substance
to fall into enemy hands,
I'll destroy it first!
They're charging weapons.
You'll destabilize
the molecules.
We'll both
be destroyed.
Then return
our technology...now!
I'm sorry.
That's not possible.
Direct hit.
Shields down ten percent.
Evasive maneuvers.
Try to shake them off.
Harmonic resonance
at maximum, Captain.
The molecules?
Eighty percent remaining.
We need to get that
down to 60.
Any damage to our power grid
could overload the chamber.
Omega would chain react.
The same thought
crossed my mind.
Where are we now?
Seventy two percent.
That's close enough!
Bridge, start
the decompression sequence.
CHAKOTAY:
Acknowledged.
What's wrong?
What's happening?
The molecules are stabilizing.
What?
I've done nothing.
It's occurring spontaneously.
That's impossible.
COMPUTER:
Decompression in 30 seconds.
Decompression in 25 seconds.
JANEWAY:
Seven, let's move!
COMPUTER:
Decompression in 20 seconds.
JANEWAY:
Seven.
COMPUTER:
Decompression in 15 seconds.
Decompression in 10 seconds.
CHAKOTAY:
Tom, are we clear
of the subspace ruptures?
Almost.
I need maximum warp
within ten seconds,
or we'll be stuck
at ground zero.
Yes, Sir.
Decompression is complete.
The harmonic chamber
has been jettisoned.
Fire!
( sighs )
We made it. We're at Warp 1.
The alien ships?
CHAKOTAY:
Out of range.
Tuvok?
TUVOK:
Sensors show no traces
of Omega molecules.
Mission accomplished.
( sighs )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
Stardate 51793.4.
We've arranged
for our guests in Sick Bay
to be taken back
to their home world,
and we can finally
put this mission behind us.
This will be
my last encrypted log
concerning the Omega Directive.
The classified data files
will now be destroyed.
I wondered who
was running my program.
Master Da Vinci
doesn't like visitors
after midnight.
He protested.
I deactivated him.
What're you
doing here, Seven?
This simulation contains
many religious components.
I was studying them...
to help me understand what
I saw in Cargo Bay 2.
The data wasn't clear
on why Omega stabilized
in the last few seconds.
But chances are it
was simply a chaotic anomaly,
nothing more.
For 3.2 seconds...
I saw perfection.
When Omega stabilized,
I felt a curious sensation.
As I was watching it,
it seemed to be watching me.
The Borg have assimilated
many species
with mythologies to explain
such moments of clarity.
I've always dismissed
them as trivial.
Perhaps I was wrong.
If I didn't
know you better...
I'd say you just had your
first spiritual experience.
( title theme playing )