KIM:
When the captain told us
to start collecting deuterium,
Seven suggested modifications
to the Bussard collectors.
Problem is, I didn't realize
the extent of the modifications
until after we'd
begun the sweep,
not that there was
anything wrong with them.
In fact, efficiency is up 23%.
In a nutshell, Harry.
The collectors
are almost full,
but I can't tell
exactly how full
until I realign my sensors
with Seven's.
Why didn't you
just say so?
Next time, work closer
with her from the start.
( sighs )
Closer. Right.
So, you're going to realign
your sensors with Seven's.
Sounds like fun.
Very funny.
( rumbling )
What was that?
Are you getting feedback
from Seven's modifications?
Negative.
Report.
I am picking up proton surges
just outside the ship.
The first was
off the port beam
and the second two were
off the starboard bow.
On screen.
There's nothing out there.
Whatever it is,
it's getting closer.
Red alert.
Janeway to Astrometrics.
SEVEN:
Yes, Captain.
Use the Astrometrics sensors
to scan for the disturbance.
I'm detecting
close-range weapons fire.
Source?
Proton surges suggest two
cloaked ships engaged in battle.
KIM:
With us caught
in the middle.
Evasive maneuvers.
PARIS: Aye, Sir.
There's a massive
power surge--
like one of the
ships is exploding.
Captain, there is one life sign
aboard that vessel.
It is no longer on our sensors.
We're being hailed--
audio only.
Let's hear it.
WOMAN:
Chakotay, please,
I need your help.
WOMAN:
Chakotay, are you reading me?
Please answer.
This is Commander Chakotay.
Who are you?
Please, anyone on Voyager,
if you can hear me,
I need help.
There has been
an explosion on the vessel.
The hull is
destabilizing.
Life support
is off-line.
Beam her directly
to sickbay.
Targeting her
coordinates.
I've lost her.
Trying again.
I don't understand.
I get a clear lock;
Then it drops out.
If we can get
an away team over there
we could stabilize her ship
and tractor it in.
Do it.
Tom, Tuvok, let's find out
what's going on.
TUVOK:
Environmental systems
are not functioning.
Oxygen levels are
dangerously low.
CHAKOTAY:
Tom... try to get
life support on-line.
No life signs.
See if you can
stabilize the hull.
I'll look for the pilot.
Hello?
( woman groans )
Can you hear me?
WOMAN:
Chakotay, is it you?
Yes.
I'm going to get
this bulkhead off you.
But the beam will fall.
I'm going to pry the bulkhead
off you.
When I say "now," get ready
to roll out of there
like your life
depended on it.
All right.
Ready?
Yes.
Now!
I knew you'd come.
Do I know you?
Chakotay to Voyager.
Two to beam directly
to sickbay.
How is she?
I'm not certain.
When I scan her, the readings
won't stay in the database.
Luckily, I'm a master
of visual diagnosis.
She has a minor concussion
and a compound tibular fracture.
Nothing life-threatening.
I can repair the damage.
Did you find out
how she knows you?
Not yet.
( groans weakly )
I can't.
She's coming around.
Don't be frightened.
You're quite safe here.
Captain... please...
I need asylum.
You must let me stay
on your ship,
and we've got
to get away from here.
They'll be coming
after me.
Slow down a minute.
I have a few questions first.
Who are you?
And how do you know
my first officer?
It's a complicated story.
I'm not...
I'm not sure...
quite how to begin.
But if you don't give me asylum,
they're going to track me down
and they're going
to take me back.
And I don't want to go.
We won't turn you over to anyone
without knowing the whole story.
Thank you.
Chakotay...
I want you
to stay with her.
She seems to trust you.
Maybe you'll be
able to find out
what this
is all about.
I hope so.
Keep me informed.
Once I've repaired
the fracture,
she'll need
some bed rest.
Will you stay with me?
Of course.
Then I'll be fine.
DOCTOR:
There.
That should do it.
I'd ask you to monitor
her vital signs,
but since
they aren't registering
I suppose there's no point.
Well... I have several days
worth of inoculation records
to get to catalog.
I suppose I'll get to it.
Is he gone?
Yes.
Then we're alone.
In a manner of speaking.
Can you start clearing up
a few things now?
I'll try.
It's complicated.
You see, we've met before.
If that were true,
I'm sure I'd remember.
No, you wouldn't.
You couldn't.
You see,
the memories of my people
can't be held in the minds
of other races.
When we encounter others
which we do...
infrequently
they remember us
for a few hours...
but then the memories fade away.
We're completely forgotten
by the next day.
Is this done through technology?
Telepathy?
It's a factor of our biology.
You see, our bodies produce
a sort of pheromone
which blocks the long-term
memory engrams of others.
Is that why the tricorder
can't scan you?
Why we couldn't get
a transporter lock?
We're impervious
to those sort of devices.
Your ships are cloaked as well.
When you live a covert existence
you develop technology
to enhance it.
But you say we've met before.
About a month ago.
I spent several weeks here.
Several weeks...
you and I worked
closely together.
You helped me
a great deal.
Then I left...
knowing that you would forget
everything about me.
Then why did you come back?
Why the battle?
Why ask us for asylum?
I know you want everything
in a nutshell.
That's the way you work.
But I have to tell you
the whole story
before it will
make sense.
Fine. I'm listening.
I came back...
because I fell in love with you.
She comes from Ramura.
It's a closed society
that won't tolerate
anybody trying to leave.
Apparently, she was
disenchanted with that,
and wanted out.
They're trying
to bring her back.
That's why she's asking
for asylum.
But you say
that she claims
she was on Voyager
before this .
About a month ago.
She says she's a "tracer"--
a kind of bounty hunter
who tracks down people
who try to leave their world.
She found a runaway
hiding on Voyager.
She was here,
but nobody remembers it?
That's what she says,
but I think we have to find
a way to verify her story.
I was looking
at her ship.
It uses a sophisticated
polarization technique
that causes our sensor scans
to pass right through it.
She could have been shadowing us
for quite a while.
And learned enough about
us to convince us she's
been here before.
But why?
Why go to that trouble?
What about the battle with
that other cloaked ship?
She put herself in danger,
when it would have
been a lot easier
simply to ask for asylum.
I agree...
but I think
we have to make sure
she doesn't have
some hidden agenda.
If she was here, there should
be some evidence of it.
She said a computer
virus was planted
to wipe all references
to her being here
but I have to believe
we can at least turn up
some evidence of tampering.
Harry, Tuvok, Tom
do the same
with her ship.
See if the navigational logs
support what she's saying.
Gentlemen.
I agree we should
take precautions
but you seem very
suspicious of her.
I want to make sure
we're not being manipulated.
I agree. If we grant her asylum
we'll be in the position
of having to protect her.
If we're going
to commit to that,
we should certainly find out
if she's telling the truth.
I'd appreciate
your thoughts on that.
Aye, Captain.
I have successfully downloaded
the navigational
logs from your vessel.
Good. Now, compare them
with your own logs
over the last
two months.
Display Voyager's route
toward the alpha quadrant.
Now overlay my route.
There, you see?
Our ships traveled together
for at least two weeks.
You could have falsified
your navigational logs.
There is no proof that
you ever came aboard Voyager.
That's what I always liked
about you two--
such unyielding logic,
such refreshing skepticism.
Run a diagnostic on my logs.
You'll find
they haven't been altered.
( door opening )
How's it going?
TUVOK:
Her story seems
to be legitimate,
but there are
further steps to take.
Then take them.
I thought you might like
to get something to eat--
unless your memories
of our mess hall aren't good.
As a matter of fact, I was
quite fond of Neelix's food.
Now, that's something
that's hard to believe.
Commander Chakotay's
face became flushed
as he spoke with her.
What does that signify?
I'd rather not engage
in speculation.
It is a dangerous pastime.
I think our guest
will enjoy this, Commander.
Uh, fried soy meal,
buttered carrots
and a delightful
almond pudding.
Sounds wonderful.
Very nice. Thanks, Neelix.
You were very diplomatic.
Why do you say that?
You hate carrots,
fried food upsets your stomach,
and you refuse to eat pudding
because you think it's slimy.
Right?
I'm curious.
When you were here before,
you said we worked together,
but you also said you were here
to retrieve a runaway.
How was I involved?
Aren't you more curious
to hear about
how we fell in love?
"We"? You said you
were in love with me.
You didn't say I
felt the same way.
If you hadn't returned
the feelings
do you really think
I would have taken
such a terrible risk
to get back to you?
Let's take it
one step at a time.
How did you get on our ship?
That was easy. The hard part
was looking for the runaway
without anyone finding me.
I managed two days on the ship
before I triggered
an intruder alert
and lost my cloak.
And then what happened?
And then I met you.
Wrong direction.
I don't want to hurt you.
Put your weapon down.
On my ship,
I give the orders.
Put yours down.
I don't mean you any harm.
You have a stowaway
on board.
I'll retrieve him,
and we'll be on our way.
That's not the way
we do things here.
Chakotay to Tuvok,
I'm in cargo bay two.
I have our intruder.
Understood, Commander.
You're about to find
yourself outnumbered.
If you want
to give me your weapon
and explain what's going on,
I'll listen.
I felt an attraction right away
but I couldn't afford
to get distracted.
I had work to do.
And I didn't know
if you felt it, too.
What happened next?
You took me to Captain Janeway.
I explained the situation.
She didn't like the idea
of a stowaway
on her ship,
so she told you and Tuvok
to work with me
to flush him out.
And did we?
You keep trying
to jump to the end.
You're skipping
all the parts about us.
And you keep trying
to talk about your feelings.
I'd rather you
stick to the events,
not the emotions
surrounding them.
Why?
Does it make you uncomfortable?
I don't want to play this game.
I've been assigned
to talk to you --
to figure out whether or not
you're telling the truth.
Even if you are,
I have no memory of meeting you
and I certainly have no memory
of feeling anything for you.
You might remember
a relationship
between us,
but as far as I'm concerned,
it didn't exist.
I see.
I'm sorry.
I just want to make
it clear how I feel.
Of course.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Can I have your pudding?
( laughing )
Gladly.
Then you're forgiven.
JANEWAY:
Chakotay and Kellin,
report to the Bridge
immediately.
It's the tracers.
They've found me.
We don't detect any ships.
I'm assuming these are
your people in cloaked vessels.
They've come
to take me back.
Harry, hail them.
They won't answer.
KIM:
She's right, captain.
No response.
Their weapons are going
through our shields
as if they weren't there.
Match shields to the frequency
of their
particle beams.
No effect.
Shield strength down to 29%.
They'll keep firing
until you surrender
or until I contact them
and agree to come back.
Do you still want to stay?
Yes.
All right.
Tom, get us out of here.
That last volley
damaged our propulsion systems.
We have thrusters only.
Captain, if you'll
let me have access
to your sensor systems
I can modify them
to detect the ships.
Do it.
This is the moment,
Chakotay.
Either we give her up
or we fire back.
Which one is it?
Fire.
I think you might be able
to detect them now
but only for
a minute or two.
Harry.
Affirmative.
Two heavily armed ships
off the port bow.
Can we get them on screen?
That's the best I can do.
JANEWAY:
Tuvok,
target their weapons systems.
Firing.
JANEWAY:
Well done.
Stand down red alert.
Well, it seems we've
granted you asylum.
Now you'll have to
give some thought
to what you want to do.
I'd prefer to remain on board.
Consider that carefully.
We're heading
for the alpha quadrant.
Before long, we will be
so far from your world,
that if you change your mind,
you wouldn't be able
to get back.
I won't change my mind,
but I must warn you--
the tracers won't give up
that easily.
Your ship is still at risk.
Nothing we haven't
faced before.
KELLIN:
I was only able to make
a temporary modification
to your sensors.
If you'd let me access
your Astrometric processors
I could make
that modification permanent.
You'll need a command
officer with you
to override
the security lockouts.
I can do that, Captain.
Go ahead.
Tom, coordinate
with Engineering
to get the propulsion systems
back on-line.
I'm on it, Captain.
We'll have to climb
up to deck ten.
Is something wrong?
I can't relax
until we're far enough away
that they realize
they can't get me back...
and to my knowledge,
that's never happened before.
There's always
a first time.
I have a high
security clearance.
They'll be afraid
I'm going to do
exactly what I'm about to do--
show you how to detect them.
Look at it this way.
If they do figure out
we can spot them,
they might realize they
aren't going
to be able to take you back.
You're such a kind person.
It's what
I remembered most.
It's what made me
turn around and come back.
And sometime...
you might be interested in...
hearing about
our last night together.
Evening, Commander.
Craving
a late-night snack?
No. Something
to help me sleep.
Got any ideas?
I know humans think
warm milk will do it.
Frankly, I find it repulsive.
I agree.
What's available
in the tea area?
Herbal is best.
I have several
Terran varieties, uh...
as well as some
more exotic blends.
Just mix me up whatever
you think is the most relaxing.
Problems?
Forgive me.
I wasn't trying to pry.
I know that.
I'm just not sure
how to answer you.
How's our guest
adapting to life on Voyager?
Quite well, I think.
She must be happy
to be here.
I'm sure she is.
Forgive me, Commander...
but sometimes it's best
to be straightforward.
It's obvious
how she feels about you--
to me, at least.
I see how she looks at you.
Might that be the source
of your consternation?
She says she, or rather, we,
fell in love when
she was here before.
Since I can't
remember any of that
I don't know if it's true
but somehow,
it's hard to believe.
Why is that?
I don't know.
It just doesn't seem like me.
I'm still suspicious of her.
I don't know
if she's using me in some way
just for her own purposes.
You don't trust her.
Not really.
May I suggest...
that maybe it's yourself
you don't trust,
your own feelings
that you're afraid of.
Sweet dreams.
( door chimes )
I couldn't sleep.
I need to talk to you.
May I come in?
I was just wondering if you
still had doubts about me,
or if you believe what
I told you about us.
Your story seems
to have been verified.
I believe
you're telling the truth.
And the rest of it?
What about us?
I'm not one to hold back
as you may have noticed,
so I'll get to the point.
I came here because of you.
I knew you wouldn't
remember me,
but I was sure
we could regain
the feelings
we had before.
They were there...
and they were real...
but now I'm not so sure.
My being here puts
this ship at risk.
It's better for everyone
if I go back to Ramura.
So please be honest.
If you feel nothing for me...
just tell me...
and I'll leave.
Don't go.
( both laughing )
It's called "ice cream"?
I'm surprised
you didn't have any
the last time you were here.
I could eat
this every day.
Then, you should.
( chuckling )
Voyager's a very...
powerful ship.
And very fast.
We've met people
with ships that are faster
and more powerful
but Voyager's always
managed to be a match
for the best of them.
Ramuran vessels are fast.
They could stay up
with this ship.
Kellin...
we'll keep you safe.
That's a promise.
A tracer never goes
home empty-handed.
The disgrace
would be too great.
When I was here before
I'd been tracking that
man for almost a year.
But you know all the tricks.
You can use them
against anyone
who tries to come after you.
You said
you were going to tell me
about our last night together.
Let me show you.
You were sitting here
in this chair...
and I...
was here.
And we were drinking
something with bubbles.
Champagne?
Yes. I wanted to celebrate.
I'd caught my runaway that day
with your help.
How was that?
You came up with the idea
of using a magneton sweep
to disrupt his
polarization cloak.
We knew he'd be watching me
closely so... we tricked him.
I'm sorry you didn't get
your fugitive.
He must have jumped
to another ship
while Voyager was in
orbit of Mikah last week.
I'll find him eventually.
If you think we can be
of any more help, let me know.
Thank you, Commander.
This is my problem.
I'll handle it from now on.
Just beam me back to my ship
and I'll backtrack to Mikah.
Goodbye and thank you again.
Ready to energize.
Hello, Resket.
You were a real challenge.
CHAKOTAY:
I haven't had the chance
to welcome you to Voyager.
Too bad you'll be
leaving so soon.
We put him in the brig.
Once I used
the neurolytic emitter on him,
he was only too happy
to be going home again.
"Neurolytic emitter"?
We use it on runaways.
It wipes their memories
of the outside world.
So we were celebrating?
You'd become much more than
a friend to me, but I knew
I had to go home, and you'd
forget about me within hours.
So I took the initiative.
More than usual?
Oh, yes.
I moved closer to you...
I thanked you profusely
for all your help,
told you that I couldn't
have done it without you...
and I touched you.
I told you I...
I cared very much for you...
and that I wanted something
to remember you by.
And then I did this...
That's when I knew
you felt the same way.
But it didn't matter
because I still had to go.
But now you don't.
If Kellin's going
to be with us
the Captain wants her
to serve a function--
to contribute in some way.
A reasonable expectation.
What are her skills?
Basically, she was a security
operative for her people.
She's a trained expert
in weaponry,
surveillance, fighting skills.
Any idea
where she might fit in?
Mr. Neelix could use
an assistant in the mess hall.
Tuvok, that was a joke.
Don't deny it--
you were trying to be funny.
If you choose to interpret
my remark as humorous,
that is your decision.
I do and it was.
It's perfectly logical.
All the qualities you mentioned
would help in defending Neelix
against the periodic
wrath of the crew.
( laughs )
Maybe so. But don't you
think she'd be better off,
as a member
of your security detail?
Perhaps. I'll assign
her to a team
and let her
observe for a week.
At the end of that time
I'll evaluate her situation.
Good enough.
Commander, I've been giving
some thought to the fact
that the Ramuran ships
might be in pursuit
and could attack us again.
I've given that
some thought myself.
Their proton weapons were
particularly effective
against us.
If Kellin would work
with Seven and Ensign Kim,
perhaps we could devise
a strategy to defend ourselves.
I'm sure she'd be happy
to do that.
Have her report
to Astrometrics at 1300 hours.
I've downloaded data
from our tactical logs.
You can access it
from this console.
Our weapons are
proton-based particle beams
very tightly focused.
It's like being hit with
thousands of needles.
They can penetrate
any shield
even if the modulations
are changed.
Very clever.
No defense has ever
stopped these weapons.
Then maybe we're
about to make history.
You've found a way
to counteract them?
I think so.
The trick is to scatter
those beams a little,
make it harder for them
to penetrate the shields.
I think we could do that
by tying the baryon sensors
into deflector control.
Here's what I have in mind.
Why don't you look this over
and let me know what you think?
I'll do it right away.
By the way, I hear Chakotay
recommended you to Tuvok
to serve on a security detail.
I want to help out
in some way.
A word of advice.
Volunteer for beta squad.
They're the best team.
You'll learn a lot from them.
I will. Thank you.
When you mentioned
Commander Chakotay's name
she flushed.
He did the same
when he saw her.
What are you saying?
I suspect the commander
and Kellin are engaged
in a courtship ritual.
It seems an unnecessary
and complicated precursor
to the act of procreation.
( chuckles )
I know you think so,
but trust me,
some people
need those rituals.
Explain.
It's...it's usually
considered a good idea
if two people get to know
each other a little
before they become... intimate.
Why is that?
Because it's more comfortable.
Uh, you spend some time
together, you laugh, you talk.
And that makes it easier to...
to get closer.
But the end result is the same,
is it not?
Well, I guess so.
Then I fail to see what is
accomplished by all the talk.
Seven, if you don't get it,
then I can't explain it to you.
Obviously.
I should have known.
They must have gotten somebody
on board during the battle.
You're jumping
to conclusions.
No. There's a tracer.
He's here, he's come for me.
That broken vase
was a warning.
We'll protect you.
I'm not going to let
anything happen to you.
It's too late.
No!
We can use
the same magneton sweep
we used to flush out Resket.
We'll find this one
and send him on his way.
( energy crackling )
I'm afraid
I can't let that happen.
Curneth, don't.
Chakotay to Security.
Intruder alert,
my quarters.
Please, I beg you,
don't do this.
You know better
than to ask that, Kellin.
No!
CHAKOTAY:
Drop it! Drop it!
You're too late.
She's already
beginning to forget
everything that's happened here.
( gasping lightly )
The doctor says
there's nothing he can do.
Your recent memories
have already begun to fade.
Don't let this happen,
please.
Don't let this happen.
Do you have any idea
how we can reverse the effect?
Promise me...
if I forget why I'm here,
if I forget you...
do what I did...
and you'll tell me
all about us...
and you'll help me to remember.
I will, but I'm going
to try to do more than that.
Can the effects
of the neurolytic emitter
be reversed?
Reversed?
I have no idea.
As far as I know,
no one's ever tried.
Then I'll be the first.
Tell me how the emitter works,
how it affects
the memory centers.
You sound desperate,
Commander.
Does Kellin mean
that much to you?
What you're doing is wrong;
She wants to stay here.
This is futile.
Even if I knew
how the emitter works
I wouldn't tell you.
You have no right
to do this.
I have every right.
The laws on our world
are very specific about that.
No one may leave.
No one may reveal
anything about us
to the outside world.
Kellin has violated
both of those edicts.
Returning her will
serve as a deterrent
to others who might
think of leaving.
Did it ever occur to you
that the fact that
so many people want to leave
might mean there's something
wrong with your society?
We have a strong
and cohesive society
because of our efforts
to keep it that way.
A few runaways among millions
hardly indicates a problem.
If there are so few...
why not let them go?
That would suggest that
we don't care about them.
What a terrible message.
You may have wiped her memory,
but Kellin's not going back.
Maybe we should wait
and see if that's what happens.
She made it clear to me
that she wants to stay here.
So maybe you
should start practicing
what you're going
to tell your superiors.
( sighs )
Yes?
( door opening )
The doctor told me
he'd released you.
How are you feeling?
I'm fine.
Do I know you?
Yes.
At least, you did.
You'll have to forgive me,
but I don't remember
how I got here
or anything else
that's happened
in at least
the past few weeks.
I know.
I hope I wasn't
throwing things
in a fit of rage.
No.
I assume a tracer
is here to take me back.
That's right.
But...
what I'm going to say
will sound strange,
but it's what you
asked me to do
before you lost
your memories.
You came here
about a month ago
looking for a runaway.
After you left with him,
you decided to come back.
But if I finished
my assignment,
why would I come back here?
Because...
you'd fallen
in love with me.
Forgive me.
You're certainly attractive,
but what you're telling me
seems very unlikely.
But it's what happened.
We started to
work together...
and I began to realize
how unique you are.
Before long, I couldn't
get you out of my mind.
Are you saying that you fell
in love with me as well?
Yes.
And then we realized
the tracer was on board.
After he used
the emitter on you,
you made me promise
to tell you all of this
so you would know what
happened between us.
This is a little unsettling.
What is it
you want from me?
Kellin,
don't go back
with the tracer.
Stay here for a while,
at least for a few days.
We can get to know
each other again.
I honestly can't imagine
what would be served by that.
I have to go home.
If you stayed...
you might change
your mind.
Then that's
all the more reason
that I should leave now.
I've violated one
of our most important edicts...
and I wouldn't want
to make that mistake again.
I wish...
I wish we had met
under different circumstances.
( sighs )
Your ship's ready.
Thank you, Commander.
I've implanted
a computer virus
to eliminate any reference
to our being here.
By tomorrow afternoon
you'll have forgotten
everything.
It will be as though
we never existed.
It's better that way.
You're such a kind person.
I won't forget that.
I wish you both the best.
Energize.
First officer's personal log,
stardate 51813.4.
Maybe it would be best,
as the tracer said,
to forget about Kellin
and the time she spent here
but I don't want to do that.
I want to remember.
More coffee, Commander?
No, thanks.
I'm almost done.
Mmm.
Strange to see you using
those ancient
writing implements.
Ah, it's the only way
I could get a permanent record
of what's happened
in the last few days.
I want to get it down
before I forget it all.
I'm sorry things
didn't work out for you.
( sighs )
I've been trying
to make sense of it.
I fell in love with her twice.
I thought she could do the same.
We were the same two people
on the same ship.
Why didn't it happen again?
I keep going over and over
our last conversation,
trying to think if there was
something I could have said,
could have done...
but nothing comes to mind.
Commander, I don't think
you can analyze love.
It's the greatest mystery
of all.
No one knows why it happens
or doesn't.
Love is a chance combination
of elements.
Any one thing might be enough
to keep it from igniting.
A mood, a glance...
a remark.
And if we could define love...
predict it...
it would probably lose
its power.
I'll let you finish.
Good night.