When diplomacy fails,
there's only one alternative--
violence.
Force must be applied
without apology.
It's the Starfleet way.
Then our philosophies
are in agreement.
Will you help us?
You're asking me
to fight your war,
destroy your enemy.
I'm asking you
to intimidate the Kyrians
with your technology...
help me capture their leader.
This ship
has superior firepower.
He won't risk a conflict
with you.
We risk life and limb
so your people
can annex Kyrian land.
Sounds like a
good deal for you.
What do we get?
A way home.
You know more about Voyager
than you've let on.
Your reputation in this
Quadrant precedes you.
That's why we
sought you out.
I'm listening.
There's a cyclic wormhole
five days' journey from here.
We know where it is
and we can help you
stabilize it.
If you are lying...
How far do you have to go?
60,000 light-years?
I want all tactical data
regarding your little war:
Kyrian defenses,
the position of
your own forces,
everything.
You'll have it
within the hour.
( alarm blaring )
Eight Kyrian fighter-ships
approaching.
Arm the assault probes.
Fire at will.
Hail them.
Channel open.
This is Captain Janeway
of the warship Voyager.
Break off your attack,
or I'll destroy you.
TUVOK:
They are
not responding.
( rumbling )
They're returning fire.
Shields are holding.
Chako-tay, any luck
tracking down their leader?
Not yet.
We think Tedran has
gone into hiding.
JANEWAY:
I thought he might.
We'll have to flush him out.
What do you suggest?
Biogenic weapons.
We'll infect
the most populated
Kyrian territories.
The Doctor's nearly done
working on the weapon.
Our conflict is with Tedran
himself, not with his people.
They're innocent.
The best way
to bring down a ruler
is to make his people suffer.
Captain...
This is no time
for half-measures.
You wanted victory.
You're going to get it.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Status?
We have established
a datalink
between my neural net
and the phaser array.
I am reconfiguring the beam
to carry a bio-agent
into the planet's atmosphere.
JANEWAY:
When will it be ready?
It is ready now, Captain.
Phasers are on line.
Target the first city.
And fire.
MALE:
The Warship Voyager--
one of the most powerful vessels
of its time.
Armed with photonic torpedoes
and particle weapons,
this ship of destruction
could wipe out an entire
civilization within hours.
On this particular day
in history, we were lucky.
The death toll
could've been much worse.
By the time Voyager
targeted our major cities,
Tedran had already begun
an evacuation.
Thousands of lives
were saved.
Unfortunately, it was
only the beginning
of Captain Janeway's onslaught.
As you'll see,
her actions would have a
lasting effect on our world.
Even today, 700 years later,
we are still feeling the impact
of the Voyager encounter.
Before we continue
the simulation,
I'd like to answer
any questions you might have.
I'm curious about
Voyager itself.
How many people
were on board?
We believe
they had a complement
of over 300 soldiers.
Did they attack
other worlds, as well?
Well, we aren't certain.
Records of Voyager's travels
through our Quadrant
are incomplete,
but it's safe to assume
that they interfered
with many other cultures, yes.
Tell us more about
the Borg drones
they kept on the ship.
Voyager had many weapons
at their disposal,
including species they'd
assimilated along the way:
Borg, Talaxian, Kazon.
They were captured
and made to work
as part of Voyager's
fighting force.
Let's resume the simulation,
and you can see
for yourself.
It's a few hours after
the initial bombardment.
Janeway and her squadron
are on the Bridge,
mounting their assault.
Now, what you
are about to see
is graphic and unsettling.
Status.
Status!
Approximately
3,000 Kyrians dead.
JANEWAY:
That's it?
TUVOK:
The bio-agent
is still dispersing
through the atmosphere.
The fatality rate
will be 300,000
soon enough.
How soon?
Best guess--
one hour.
Why do you always
keep me waiting, Tuvok?
My apologies.
Preparing to fire again.
Double the yield.
Captain, don't you think
that's excessive?
You picked a bad time
to have second thoughts,
Ambassador.
I want them defeated,
but... but this is genocide.
Defeat? Genocide?
Why quibble with semantics?
This wasn't our agreement.
We're going to defeat
the Kyrians
and you're going to keep up
your end of the bargain.
( rumbling )
Ensign,
confine this gentleman
to the brig.
I'll let you know
when it's over.
Three more
Kyrian vessels approaching.
Evade them.
Aye, aye, sir.
The location?
Look... I can keep
this up all day.
Tell the Commander
what he wants to know.
Maybe I can't keep
this up all day.
I'm a man of peace.
My native people
are enlightened...
nonviolent...
much like your own.
I'm saddened that this
has happened to you.
If we can work together,
maybe we can end
this conflict.
Stand aside, Chako-tay.
Let me hit him.
That hyperspanner
would cause
an unacceptable
level of damage.
I remind you--
he must still
be able to speak.
What do you have in mind?
This neural solvent--
a clean and efficient
inducer of pain--
far more effective
than your crude
attempts at persuasion.
No doubt you are experiencing
a tingling sensation
behind your eyes.
The chemical is dissolving
your optic nerves.
I'll ask you again.
Where is Tedran?
DOCTOR:
The pain will increase
exponentially
until your cerebral
cortex begins to liquefy.
I can reverse
the process...
if ordered to do so.
And I want to give
that order.
But you have
to tell me...
where is Tedran?
CHAKOTAY:
He's here, at
these coordinates.
Assuming our prisoner
told you the truth.
Oh, believe me, he was
very cooperative at the end.
Neelix?
I'm reading
a fortified compound
1.6 kilometers
beneath the surface.
Chako-tay,
you and Tuvok
take an assault team
and find Tedran.
Make sure he's escorted
safely to Voyager.
Yes, sir.
( rumbling )
What now?
Intruders. Four Kyrians just
beamed into the Engine Room.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Engineering.
Respond.
They've erected
force fields.
Our soldiers can't get in.
They've left me no choice.
Computer...
initiate the Borg
activation sequence.
COMPUTER:
Sequence in progress.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Seven of Nine.
State your instructions.
A group of Kyrians
is in the Engine Room.
Stop them.
We understand.
Resistance is futile.
Seven of Nine to the Bridge.
The Kyrian threat
has been neutralized.
Acknowledged.
Two of the Kyrians
are still alive.
What shall we do with them?
Well, you've been wanting
to expand your fighting force.
Assimilate them.
We understand.
I just received word
from the attack team.
Good news, Lieutenant?
Very.
They've captured Tedran
and one of his aides.
They're heading back
to Voyager.
Take them to Chamber 19
and get the
Vaskan Ambassador.
This is one negotiation
he won't want to miss.
Welcome aboard.
I appreciate
your hospitality.
Are all your guests
treated so well?
Well, it's not every day
that we receive
such an important visitor--
the great Tedran...
a man of wisdom and peace...
a servant of his people.
Well, your people need you,
now more than ever.
State your demands.
Tell your forces to stand down,
and I'll call off my attack.
I understand
what the Vaskans want--
more of our territory...
more resources.
But what do you want,
Captain?
Why are you
doing this to us?
He's offered my crew a way home.
To reach your home,
you would destroy ours?
That's right.
And you'd do the same
in my position.
No, I would not.
Spoken like a true martyr.
You're very enlightened.
But are you so proud...
that you'd let your people die
before you'd humble yourself?
Tell them to surrender.
You have shamed us all.
We could've
ended this on our own...
peacefully...
without her.
Surrender.
No.
We will prevail.
JANEWAY:
Don't look so shocked,
Ambassador.
This is what you wanted,
isn't it?
The ensuing conflict
was brief but brutal--
two million Kyrians
slaughtered within days.
The Warship Voyager
continued on its way,
leaving the Kyrian
dynasty in ruins.
The Vaskan leaders proceeded
to occupy our lands,
forcing my people
into subservience.
It took centuries for us
to undo the damage
that Captain Janeway
had done.
And the Kyrian struggle
for equality is far from over.
This simulation
and this museum
are a testament
to that struggle.
I hope you found
your experience here worthwhile.
If you'd like to learn
more about Voyager
and its role
in the history of our planet,
I suggest you explore
the rest of this exhibit.
Thank you for your time.
MALE:
Please, feel free
to try the simulation.
MALE 2:
Oh, thank you
very much.
I wouldn't touch
that if I were you.
One of the Voyager's
torpedoes--
25-isoton yield.
It could destroy an entire
city within seconds.
It's been inactive
for centuries,
but you never know.
No, I'm only teasing,
but, please, be careful.
If we damage any
of these relics,
they can never
be replaced.
The history of our people
should be respected.
I have a question
about that history.
Please.
How can you prove
that it's true?
Take a closer look.
The evidence is
all around you.
Some musty fossils
and a re-creation?
That doesn't
prove anything.
I disagree.
You're trying to
blame the Vaskans
for all your troubles,
the way you always do.
I don't have a problem
with your species.
I have Kyrian friends,
but I don't appreciate
seeing my people
being portrayed as villains
in your little simulation,
and I certainly don't want
your history taught
to my children.
Well, you'd better
get used to the idea,
because we've just uncovered
an artifact that's going
to confirm everything
you've seen here.
Three weeks ago,
our research team
found a data-storage device
buried nine meters
beneath the ruins at Kesef.
I've confirmed
that it came from Voyager.
Another fossil?
The device contains
active data...
possibly crew logs--
even Captain Janeway's
personal almanac.
In the next few days,
we could be hearing
Voyager's version
of these events,
in their own words!
And what if those words
tell a different story?
What then?
We will change our views
accordingly.
I'm sure you will.
I apologize.
Please, enjoy
the rest of your visit.
Activate re-creation:
"The Voyager Encounter."
Display Engine Room.
Begin dictation.
I'm resuming work
on artifact 271:
the Voyager
data-storage device.
I've decided to try
using period tools
from the simulation itself.
With any luck,
they'll be more compatible.
Hmm...
there's far more data here
than I expected.
Seems more like a program
of some sort.
Yes.
Yes!
It's an optronic datastream...
a hologram.
( staticky ):
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
I recognize you.
You're Voyager's Doctor.
What am I doing in Engineering?
Where's my mobile emitter?
You're not an android.
Of course not.
What are you talking about?
A Kyrian.
Doctor to the Bridge.
Intruder alert!
Security to Engineering!
You won't have
much luck with that.
Nothing in here is real.
It's a simulation.
A holodeck?
No.
You're in the Museum
of Kyrian Heritage.
You've stolen my program.
How?
Please...
let me try to explain.
Try quickly.
You...
are a hologram.
That I know.
Uh... I just discovered
your program
inside this data-storage device.
That's the EMH backup module.
One of your attack parties must
have taken it from Sick Bay.
Actually, we found it
at the ruins at Kesef.
I know this will be difficult
for you to accept,
but a great deal
of time has passed
since Voyager
encountered the Kyrians.
How much time?
700 years, give
or take a decade.
We're not certain.
I don't believe you.
Think about it.
When your program
is inactive,
a moment or a millennium
are the same to you.
700 years?
What about my ship?
What happened to my crew?
No one knows.
It's safe to say
they're long dead.
And I'm some sort of...
fossil?
No, not a fossil--
a witness, a living
witness to history.
There's so much we don't
know about what happened,
but you saw it.
You lived through
those times.
You helped to shape them.
Doctor, you could be the
most important discovery
of all time.
No, this isn't possible.
Doctor...
I don't believe you.
Doctor!
What's going to happen
to me now?
Will you put me on display?
The holographic
Rip van Winkle?
I'm not sure.
I want to try
to contact Starfleet...
if there still
is a Starfleet.
That will have to wait.
Wait for what?
There are other...
issues to be resolved.
What kind of issues?
You're the Voyager Doctor.
A lot of people are going
to have questions.
On our world,
artificial life-forms
are considered sentient
and responsible
for their actions.
You might have
to face charges.
Charges?
For your crimes.
You designed
the bio-weapons that
killed eight million
Kyrians.
I did nothing of the sort.
All of our evidence shows
that you were a war criminal.
Evidence? What evidence?
Like this, for example?
Triple-armored hull?
30 torpedo tubes?
25 phaser banks?
This isn't what our ship
looked like.
We reconstructed it
from a partial schematic
found in the Cyrik Ocean...
which was badly damaged
by corrosion.
We were bound to get
a few details wrong.
Voyager wasn't a warship.
We were explorers!
Yes, I know--
trying to get home, to Mars.
Earth! You see, you couldn't
even get that right!
This is a nightmare.
What if I'm
found guilty?
What's going
to happen to me?
That's up to the Arbiters.
But I imagine
the penalty would be severe.
Your program
could be decompiled.
You've got
to believe me.
To you, this may
be ancient history.
To me, it's yesterday.
You called me a living witness.
Well, at least
give me the chance
to set the record straight.
I want to see your version
of what happened.
We've already drained
two phaser banks,
and he hasn't hit anything.
If you looked at your
console once in awhile,
instead of chasing
the female ensigns,
you'd see otherwise.
KIM:
Tom's right.
This war was supposed
to be over in five minutes.
You have a better idea,
Lieutenant?
As a matter
of fact, I do.
Fighter shuttles--
a direct assault.
Led by you? Good luck.
Watch your mouth, hedgehog.
I haven't heard
a single good idea.
Well, then propose something,
First Officer.
Earn your rank for once.
CHAKOTAY:
Get away from us...
Gentlemen...
Gentlemen!
Save it for the holodeck.
We've got a war to fight.
We've only been attacking
the Kyrian military
installations-- a mistake.
We should target
the general population.
Excellent idea, Captain.
I've examined the Kyrian genome,
and they would be vulnerable
to any number of
biological weapons.
JANEWAY:
How soon could you
have one ready?
Within the hour.
Dismissed.
Pure fiction.
This is absurd.
QUARREN:
Halt re-creation.
This is a reasonable
extrapolation
from historic record.
But if you'd like
to point out any
inconsistencies...
Inconsistencies?!
I don't know
where to begin.
Granted, this looks
like the briefing room,
but these aren't
the people I knew.
No one behaved like this.
Well... aside from Mr. Paris.
We weren't
at each other's throats.
We didn't talk about
how to destroy planets.
We helped people.
We were an enlightened crew.
Are you denying these
events took place?
Yes.
Are you saying you
never got involved
in the conflict
between my people
and the Vaskans?
Yes!
Well, no, we did get involved,
but it was nothing
like this.
Elaborate.
There was a meeting
in this room,
but it wasn't
about battle tactics,
it was about a dilemma
we were facing.
We had negotiated a trade
agreement with the Vaskans.
We were dealing with
a representative, Ambassador...
Ambassador Daleth.
Daleth. Exactly.
Everything was going
according to plan...
until...
...we were attacked...
by your people, the Kyrians.
They'd picked that moment
to start a war
and we were caught
in the middle.
The Kyrians were the aggressors?
No, no, that can't be right.
Captain Janeway called
this meeting to figure out
how we could extricate ourselves
from the conflict
and still maintain the trade
agreement with the Vaskans.
But we weren't on their side,
and we certainly
never attacked you.
Save your objections until
you see the entire re-creation.
Let's continue.
We will prevail.
JANEWAY:
Don't look so shocked,
Ambassador.
This is what you wanted,
isn't it?
Somewhere-- halfway
across the galaxy, I hope--
Captain Janeway
is spinning in her grave.
You've portrayed us
as monsters.
The Captain's
a cold-blooded killer;
the crew's a gang of thugs;
and I'm a mass murderer.
Calm yourself.
Why should I?
I'm about to be hanged
for crimes I didn't commit.
Tell me your
version of events.
I remember this man.
Tedran.
He was a martyr
to our people.
Some martyr.
He led the Kyrian attack
against Voyager.
You're lying.
I was there.
You're trying to
protect yourself.
And so are you!
From the truth.
Isn't it a coincidence
that the Kyrians are
being portrayed
in the best
possible light?
Martyrs, heroes, saviors.
Obviously, events
have been reinterpreted
to make your people
feel better about themselves.
Revisionist history...
it's such a comfort.
We were not the aggressors
in the Great War.
We were the victims.
The proof can be found
anywhere on this world.
The Kyrian people are
being oppressed to this day.
The problems in your society
are none of my business.
I'm just telling you
what I saw 700 years ago.
I don't believe you,
and neither will anyone else.
What are you doing?
Shutting down your program.
Wait. Please. I...
I can prove
to you I'm right.
The medical tricorder--
the artifact
you have on display.
If you just let me...
Lies.
Begin dictation.
I've reexamined the data module
and from what I can tell, the
Doctor was telling the truth--
at least about one thing.
He is a hologram,
a backup program.
We always knew he was
an artificial life-form,
but we thought
he was an android.
If we were mistaken
about that...
I wonder if we might also
be wrong about Voyager itself.
Another question,
Why would a hologram
designed for medical purposes
be programmed to lie so readily?
From the moment I activated him,
this Doctor has insisted
that he's innocent.
At first, I...
didn't believe him.
End dictation.
Activate re-creation:
"The Voyager Encounter."
Display Medical Chamber.
( beeping )
Please state the nature
of the medical...
Oh. It's you.
You've given me a lot
to think about.
Really?
I thought you'd heard enough
of my... lies.
I judged you too quickly.
I'm sorry.
What changed your mind?
Time to think.
For your information,
I don't appreciate
being deactivated
in the middle of a sentence.
It brings back...
unpleasant memories.
It won't happen again.
Good.
Because if you don't stop
treating me
like a second-class hologram,
I won't cooperate
with your investigation.
I'm perfectly happy
to lie dormant
in that data module
for a few eons.
I didn't come here to argue.
Then what do you want?
I don't know.
To talk, I guess,
about what really happened
700 years ago.
Are you sure
you're willing to listen
to a mass-murderer like me?
I'm willing to keep
an open mind.
That's the most I can promise.
Try to understand
my point of view.
All my life, I thought
I knew the truth.
There was never any doubt.
I never meant to throw
your beliefs into doubt,
but I can't deny
what I know to be true.
I realize that now...
and I want to
know the truth.
And I want the Arbiters
to know it, too.
Well...
the stage is certainly set,
but I'll have to
rewrite the characters
and revise
the plot a little.
I'm quite adept in the art
of holographic programming.
If you'll give me access
to your technology,
maybe I can create a
simulation of my own...
show you what happened.
Don't worry, Ambassador.
We've got plenty
of medical supplies,
and we'd be more than happy
to share them with you.
Then we agree.
In exchange,
we'll provide you
with as much dilithium
as you need.
That's very generous,
Ambassador.
I'll transport
the canisters immediately.
It would be in
your best interest
to make this
exchange quickly.
Oh? Why is that?
We've been in conflict
with a neighboring species,
the Kyrians.
They've been threatening
to attack us.
War could break out
any day.
We've tried
every diplomatic option,
but the Kyrians are
a violent, stubborn people.
No problem. I understand
what you're going through.
I wish I could make you
one of our diplomats.
You might
have better luck
resolving this situation.
Under different
circumstances...
Janeway to Sick Bay.
This is the Doctor.
Ambassador Daleth and I
have reached an agreement.
Assemble the medical supplies.
Done, Captain. The supplies
are in Cargo Bay 1.
Once we transport the supplies
to the surface, there may be...
( rumbling )
TUVOK:
Red Alert.
Captain Janeway to the Bridge.
TUVOK:
We're being fired on
by three ships.
The Kyrians.
Hail them.
TUVOK:
Channel open.
This is Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
We are not your enemies.
Please break
off your attack.
They're not responding.
I'd advise you
to retreat, Captain.
Shields down
to 86 percent.
Break out of orbit.
Put some distance between us.
Yes, ma'am.
( alarm sounding )
Four intruders.
They are in Engineering.
Janeway to Engineering.
B'Elanna, respond.
Tuvok.
Take as much of their
technology as you can.
You will fail.
Drop your weapons.
Back away.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Go ahead.
The Kyrians have killed three
of the Engineering crew.
They've taken Seven of Nine
and one of the injured
crew members hostage.
They're now on Deck 2,
Section 32.
Acknowledged.
Remember your offer
to make me a diplomat?
Well, it looks like I don't
have much of a choice.
Tell the Doctor
we have casualties.
Have him meet
us on Deck 2.
Janeway to Tuvok.
We're approaching
Section 31.
TUVOK:
The evacuation of Deck 2
is complete.
Send three security
teams to this deck,
then seal all
the access points.
Acknowledged.
How typical of the Kyrians.
What do you mean?
They fight the same way
they live-- deviously.
( footsteps approaching )
Janeway to Tuvok.
Tuvok here.
The Kyrians are in
the Mess Hall. We're going in.
Security is on the way.
I'll go first, Captain,
and draw any fire, if need be.
Your crew is
heroic, Captain.
I just happen to be
invulnerable to phaser fire,
but I appreciate
the compliment. Captain?
Go.
DALETH:
Tedran...
this is between us.
Leave these people
out of it.
I know what
you're doing--
an alliance
with these aliens.
We were trading with them,
nothing more.
You expect me to believe that?
You plan to use this ship
to destroy us.
We wouldn't need help
if we wanted to destroy you.
We didn't realize you were
fighting with the Vaskans.
Now, lay down your weapons,
and I promise
you won't be harmed.
( door opens )
No!
( groans )
( tricorder beeping )
( steady tone sounds )
He's dead.
DOCTOR:
Computer, freeze program.
A tragic, needless death,
but, as you can see,
Voyager was not responsible.
After Tedran was killed,
Voyager was attacked
by nine Kyrian ships.
My program was disabled,
most likely when they
stole my backup module.
The next thing I knew,
I was standing next
to this gentleman,
seven centuries later.
Very entertaining.
I'll admit your holo-technology
is new to me.
I had to extrapolate
in a few places,
but I assure you, this is
an accurate re-creation.
Perhaps. Or perhaps
it's the fabrication
of a war criminal
who's afraid for his life.
VASKAN:
Do you have any
evidence to support
your explanation?
In fact, I do.
I've confirmed that
this is the same tricorder
I used to scan Tedran
at the moment of his death.
If I can access
the bio-readings inside,
I can prove that he was killed
by a Vaskan weapon,
not by Captain Janeway.
Can this be done?
I've been trying to decipher
the instrument for years,
but with the Doctor's help...
I fail to see what
this would prove.
Tedran died on Voyager,
a victim of a conspiracy
to oppress my people.
The weapon used,
who fired it--
this is all
beside the point.
Was there a conspiracy?
Did Voyager really help
my ancestors
to start the Great War,
or were Kyrians
the aggressors,
as my people
have always believed?
No, this casts
doubt on everything.
But it doesn't change
the fact that my children
can't attend the same
academies as yours,
or that we are forced to live
outside of the city center.
Today's problems
are not at issue here.
This is about history.
Look, I don't know
who started your war.
All I'm saying is that
Voyager wasn't responsible.
I can't believe
that you would cooperate
with this murderer--
you, of all people.
You built this museum.
The facts are
turning out to be
more complex
than I expected.
We shouldn't be listening
to this hologram.
I want him arrested
and charged
for the crimes
we know he committed.
That's not your decision
to make.
No, it's not, is it?
I'm only on
this commission
because you needed
a token Kyrian.
Please.
This isn't about race.
It's always about race.
You seize every
opportunity
to keep yourselves
in power.
I'm sorry you see it that way.
I think we are obligated
to hear what the Doctor
has to say.
Proceed with your investigation.
Yes, Arbiter.
You'll pay for your crimes.
700 years,
and I'm still caught
in the middle
of your little dispute.
One might have hoped
for a bit of social progress
in the interim.
Change never comes
easily for us.
Humph. That's
an understatement.
I've entered the
specifications
that you gave me.
Let's give it a try.
Close enough.
This diagnostic tool
should help me get past
the initial
encryption sequences.
Too bad we can't re-create
B'Elanna Torres.
Torres... the Chief
Transporter Operator.
Chief Engineer.
You might want to make
the correction
in your history books.
What was she like-- Torres?
I suppose we've gotten
her personality wrong, too.
Starting to believe
me, are you?
Well, let's just say I'm
trying to keep an open mind.
B'Elanna Torres...
intelligent, beautiful,
and with a chip
on her shoulder
the size of
the Horsehead Nebula.
She also had
a kind of vulnerability
that made her...
quite endearing.
You miss her...
and the others.
From my perspective,
I saw them all
only a few days ago.
But in fact,
it's been centuries.
And I'll never see them again.
Did they ever reach home?
I wonder.
I've always wondered that, too.
From as far back
as I can remember.
Really?
Ever since
I was a small child,
the first time I heard
the name Voyager,
it conjured up
my imagination.
Even though we were
the bad guys?
That didn't matter.
I was too young
to understand
the implications.
The fact that you were
so far from home,
traveling across the stars.
Oh, I found it all very heroic.
I suppose Voyager
is what made me fall in love
with history.
If it means anything to you,
you would have made
a fine member of our crew.
( rumbling )
I hope that's part
of the simulation.
No, it isn't.
( glass shattering )
( people shouting )
( glass shattering,
shouting continues )
( all shouting )
( screaming )
No! Stop this!
We know about the hologram!
This museum's
filled with lies!
Stop! Listen to me!
We've listened long enough!
They're using photon grenades.
We've got to take cover.
This way.
( distant weapons fire
and explosions )
What's happening?
I've been hearing weapons.
It's getting worse.
Protests, vandalism...
two people have been killed.
Don't worry. They've
cordoned off the museum.
We're safe for now.
That's not
what I'm concerned about.
Two deaths, a race riot,
all because of me?
You were only the catalyst.
The pressure's been
building for years.
It was only a matter of time
before something set it off.
Have you found
the tricorder?
Not yet.
It's crucial that we do.
The Kyrians are demanding you
be punished for your crimes,
but the Vaskans want to hear
your version of events again.
They want to continue
the investigation.
What's going to happen?
I don't know.
The Vaskans are more powerful,
but the Kyrians are very angry.
They're talking
about another war.
Then there's only one solution.
Delete my program.
I've become a kind of symbol
for this conflict.
As long as I'm around,
your people are going
to keep on fighting.
I'll show you
how to decompile my program.
You can say I was damaged
in the attack last night.
No one will hold
you responsible.
I can't do that to you.
Then I'll do it myself.
No!
I'm a medical hologram...
programmed to do no harm,
but I'm doing harm
on a global scale.
Ever since you reactivated
me, I've been concerned
with clearing
Voyager's good name.
But that's not important now.
There's more at stake.
A few days ago, I might
have agreed with you.
But what about the facts?
Facts be damned!
Names, dates, places--
it's all open to interpretation.
Who's to say
what really happened?
And ultimately,
what difference does it make?
What matters is today and
the future of your people.
Doctor, you were there.
You can't deny what happened.
I can... and I will.
Tedran was a martyr
for your people, a hero,
a symbol of your struggle
for freedom.
Who am I to wander in
700 years later
and take that away from you?
History has been abused!
We keep blaming each other
for what happened in the past.
If you don't help us now,
it could be another 700 years.
Let's find that tricorder.
It was a pivotal moment
in our history.
As a result
of the Doctor's testimony,
a dialogue was opened
between our peoples.
Eventually, we found
a new respect
for our divergent cultures
and traditions.
The efforts of people
like Quarren and the Doctor
paved the way for unity.
Quarren died six years later,
but he lived long enough
to witness the Dawn of Harmony.
And the Doctor...
well, he served as our Surgical
Chancellor for many years,
until he decided to leave.
He took a small craft
and set a course
for the Alpha Quadrant,
attempting to trace
the path of Voyager.
He said he had a longing...
for home.
This way.