( dramatic theme playing )
( equipment
powering down )
Ship is gray,
Captain.
We've cut power
to Decks 4 through 9.
Replicators,
holodecks,
and all other nonessentials
are off-line.
Remaining systems
are operating
at 20 percent
capacity.
Tom, how long can
you keep us flying?
With the deuterium
supply this low,
even at
one-quarter impulse,
we'll be out of gas
inside a week.
Everyone,
redouble your efforts.
Keep your eyes open
for new sources of deuterium.
Tuvok,
Chakotay,
I want recommendations
for further methods
of conservation.
Harry, you and I will
give them a hand in Geophysics,
see if we can't
synthesize
a substitute fuel.
In the meantime,
we stay in gray mode.
If anybody's got any other
ideas, I'm listening.
PARIS:
We could set up
a bicycle
in the mess hall,
attach a generator, pedal home.
Now,
why didn't I think of that?
And I volunteer Harry
to take the first shift.
( scoffs )
( chuckles )
Living space
will be extremely limited.
Take only
those personal items
which are absolutely essential.
( grunting )
Hello, there!
What, may I ask,
is this?
That, Mr. Vulcan,
is the
Selected Works of Jirex.
Only essential items,
Mr. Neelix.
Oh,
Jirex is essential.
He's the greatest writer
in the Talaxian canon.
I never go to sleep
without reading
at least one
of his parables.
A habit you will have
to break,
until we're able to restore
power to crew quarters.
I suppose I can try.
And...these?
I-I get terrible
neck pains without them.
I suggest
you ask the doctor
to prescribe
an anti-inflammatory.
( sighs )
Oh, fine.
I don't mind roughing it.
Mr. Neelix,
the blankets.
No. No, that's where
I draw the line.
My mother knitted
these herself.
I've slept with them
since I was a child.
You'll have to make do
with standard-issue bedding.
But those Starfleet blankets
give me a rash.
Then I suggest
you ask the doctor--
For some
anti-itch cream.
I might as well sleep
in Sickbay!
Thank you, Mr. Vulcan.
You've just
given me an idea.
( tranquil theme playing )
What's going on
here?
I'm working.
You were ordered to shut down
Astrometrics an hour ago.
We can't afford
the power.
Seven,
it's inefficient.
Efficiency is relative,
Commander.
If I shut down
Astrometrics,
I won't be able to scan
for new fuel sources.
I appreciate
your efforts,
but we'll have to use
conventional scanners until--
( console beeping )
( dramatic theme playing )
Conventional scanners
would not have found this.
What?
Highly concentrated
deuterium.
Where?
Computer,
display source.
A planetoid
.4 light-years
from our
present position.
There are dense pockets
of deuterium
just beneath the surface.
Maybe so, but that's
a demon-class planet.
Demon class?
That's what
Starfleet calls it.
Also known as Class-Y.
It's got
a toxic atmosphere
filled with
thermionic radiation.
Surface temperatures
are in excess of 500 Kelvins.
Just entering a standard orbit
would be suicide.
Our situation is desperate.
True.
When faced with
desperate circumstances,
we must adapt.
( triumphant theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
I've ordered adaptations
to our shields
to repel
the thermionic discharges.
Hoping that the benefits
will outweigh the risks,
we're now trying
to beam deuterium
from beneath
the planet's surface.
Narrow the annular confinement
beam to .47 terahertz.
Ready here,
Captain.
Stand by.
Harry, shunt whatever
additional power you can
to the containment field.
I don't want any of those
atmospheric gases
seeping in.
KIM: Aye, Captain.
[RUMBLE]
A thermionic discharge
has struck the forward shields.
They're holding.
Let's get this over with
before you tell me otherwise.
Seven, do it.
Energize.
( beeping )
Transport in progress.
Shields are weakening.
I'm reading an overload
in the pattern buffers.
Abort transport.
Controls
not responding!
Get out of there now.
Computer, seal off
the Transporter Room
and erect a level-10
containment field.
COMPUTER:
Containment field established.
( sighs )
The good news is
Nozawa and Seven of Nine
have both been treated and
released from Sickbay,
and the planetary gases
have been expelled
from the
transporter room.
And the bad news?
The transporters
are off-line.
It'll take days before
they're back again.
Great. We lose valuable
energy on a course change,
and all we get
for our trouble
is another
downed system.
Can we send a probe
to collect the deuterium?
It would incinerate
within seconds
of entering
the upper atmosphere.
Then I don't see
any other options.
Tom, put us back
on our original course.
One-quarter
impulse.
Captain,
maybe I can help.
Harry, the bicycle thing
was just a joke.
I've been thinking. With
Tuvok's shield modifications
and a few tweaks
to an environmental suit,
I could take a shuttle
to the surface
and mine the deuterium
from there.
Need I remind you, Ensign,
that there is no environment
less hospitable to humanoid life
than a Class-Y.
Actually, Tuvok, no,
you needn't remind me.
What's the
alternative?
Resume course, creep along
at quarter-impulse,
hoping we'll find fuel before
we end up dead in the water?
We've got deuterium
within arm's reach.
We can't let
the opportunity slip away
without at least trying.
He's got a point.
You wouldn't be able
to communicate with us
if you got in trouble. And until
we can get transporters back,
we couldn't beam you out.
TUVOK:
Even with
modifications,
it wouldn't be long before
your suit began to corrode.
Exposure to that atmosphere
could kill you within minutes.
I know the risks.
Even if I agreed,
I'd never let you go alone.
Of course not.
That's why I'm volunteering
my good buddy Tom
here to go with me.
( dramatic theme playing )
You were pretty forceful
in there.
So?
I don't think
I've ever seen you
that assertive
in a staff meeting
before.
You must be bucking
for a promotion.
I had an idea and I spoke up,
that's all.
Oh, no, no, no.
It was more than that.
You put Tuvok
in his place,
right in front
of everybody.
He was stating
the obvious again.
Talking down to me
like I didn't
know anything about
demon-class planets?
Oh, I am not
criticizing you.
Believe me,
nobody enjoys seeing
the Vulcan master put down
a peg more than I do.
I was just surprised,
that's all.
Why?
It didn't seem
like you.
( door beeping )
Good.
Cargo Bay 2.
You trying to change
your squeaky-clean image
or something?
Not exactly.
What, then?
How do I explain this?
( sighs )
When I first
came on board Voyager,
I was pretty green,
right?
( inhales )
A deep,
almost fluorescent green,
if I remember correctly.
I was young, inexperienced,
and I acted like it.
Nervous about giving my opinion,
hesitant to make suggestions.
So I usually just
kept my mouth shut,
and I behaved that way
for so long,
it became a habit.
But,
in the last four years,
a lot has happened.
I've fought the Borg,
been transformed into
an alien,
helped defeat the Hirogen.
Hell, I've even
come back from the dead.
( chuckles quietly )
It's been a wild ride.
I woke up the other morning,
and it suddenly hit me.
I've got a lot
of experience now,
so why should I
be afraid
to take the initiative
or voice my ideas?
( door opens )
Good for you, Harry.
But...
do me a favor.
The next time you try
to assert yourself,
leave me
out of it.
I hate
hot weather.
Don't worry,
we can cut some holes
in the
environmental suits,
get some
ventilation going.
Harry, while you're
busy improving yourself,
you might try working on
your sense of humor.
My sense of humor?
What about that stupid gag
about the bicycle?
Oh, ho, ho!
That was funny.
KIM:
No, that was not funny.
PARIS:
You think that's humorous?
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunts,
chuckles sarcastically )
I can't thank you enough
for getting me in
on this mission, Harry.
Don't mention it.
Remind me
to volunteer you to help
the next time I have to clean
the warp plasma manifolds.
Really, Tom,
you don't owe me anything.
Oh, but I do.
( console beeping )
We've lost attitude control.
Time to show off
your piloting skills.
Think you can handle it?
Heh, watch me.
Oh, I'll be watching you,
all right.
Switching to manual control.
Just sit back, relax,
and enjoy the ride.
( beeping )
We're entering
the lower atmosphere,
approaching
the landing coordinates.
All right.
I'm gonna set us down.
On my mark.
( dramatic theme playing )
( both grunting )
Mark.
You did that on purpose,
didn't you?
( chuckling )
( beeping )
It's almost
500 degrees Kelvin.
Don't worry.
The suits can handle it.
If not,
we'll be
human barbecue.
I'm picking up
traces of deuterium...
50 meters...
That way.
Let's move.
No sweat.
Lame.
( chuckling )
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
( tricorders beeping )
KIM:
It's coming from in here.
PARIS:
What is it?
Some kind of
metallic compound...
Highly viscous.
And if these
readings are right,
its temperature
is only 12 degrees?
In this
environment?
Whatever this stuff is,
it's packed with liquefied
deuterium.
Ha, ha! Jackpot.
There's another pool
20 meters that way.
Why don't you
go check it out
while I collect
a few samples here.
Right.
I don't know,
Harry...
a couple of
lounge chairs,
a big
beach umbrella,
maybe some dermalplast to
counteract the chemical burns,
and I think we've found
ourselves a new vacation spot.
( scoffs )
Aw, come on.
That was a little funny.
Let me hear you
do better.
( sighs )
( suspenseful theme plays )
Harry?
Harry!
Oh, my God.
( panting )
( grunting )
I know it's hot out,
Harry,
but you picked a lousy time
to go for a swim.
I don't know
what happened.
I leaned over
to collect a sample,
and it was like
I was pulled in.
( alarm beeps )
COMPUTER: Warning. Ensign Kim,
an environmental seal
has been compromised.
Oxygen depletion
in 30 seconds.
( both grunting )
Hang in there,
buddy,
and I'll get you back
to the shuttle.
( grunting )
PARIS:
Have you put on
weight?
KIM:
You're just
out of shape.
( alarm beeps )
COMPUTER: Warning.
Oxygen depletion
in 15 seconds.
PARIS:
I'll make you a deal.
You hold your breath
till we get back
to the shuttle,
and I promise I'll start
exercising every day.
Maybe you should start
with the bicycle.
I thought I told you
to hold your breath.
( alarm beeps )
COMPUTER: Warning.
Oxygen depletion
in five seconds.
( beeping )
Hang in there,
Harry.
We'll make it.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Lieutenant Paris,
an environmental seal
has been compromised.
Oxygen depletion
in 30 seconds.
( grunting )
You gotta be kidding me.
We're in the same boat now,
buddy,
but I'll get us
out of this.
( alarm beeps )
COMPUTER: Warning.
Oxygen depletion
in 15 seconds.
( heavy breathing )
You're right.
I definitely need
to get back in shape.
( alarm beeps )
COMPUTER: Warning.
Oxygen depletion
in five seconds.
( five beeps )
( sustained beep )
DOCTOR:
Out of the question.
NEELIX:
Be reasonable, doctor.
Take it up
with Commander Chakotay.
He's on his way
here right now.
But it's only
for a couple of days.
Just until we get
power back
in the crew quarters.
I suggest you set up camp
in the mess hall.
The mess hall
is full.
Where are we
supposed to sleep?
Anywhere but here.
This is a Sickbay,
not a dormitory.
But you have
four empty beds.
Bio-beds,
reserved for patients.
You don't have
any patients.
I may have one
in a moment,
if you and your
fellow squatters
don't go elsewhere.
You wanted to see me,
doctor?
Oh,
it's about time.
Mr. Neelix is attempting to turn
my Sickbay into a flophouse.
We are short on beds for now.
We've got to adapt.
Aha.
But...what if there's
a medical emergency?
Then Neelix and the others
will get out of the way.
Absolutely.
But...
this isn't just Sickbay.
It's my residence.
And we promise to be
the most perfect houseguests.
What more
can you ask for?
But...
I have a routine.
I'm a night owl.
What if one of them should snore
while I'm listening to Puccini?
Well, if you feel that
strongly about it, doc,
I suppose we'll have
to consider other options.
Thank you,
Commander.
For example, we could
shut down your program
until you're needed.
The Captain asked me
to look for ways
to conserve power,
and it would spare you
from having to listen
to them snore.
JANEWAY:
Commander Chakotay
to the Bridge.
On my way.
But...
( dramatic theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
Make yourselves
at home.
Try scanning for
infrared signatures.
There's too much
interference.
CHAKOTAY: What's up?
Tom and Harry still aren't back.
You want me to take another
shuttle down and look for them?
And risk losing you,
too?
Either we
keep waiting
until we run out
or deuterium
and get trapped in orbit,
or--
Or?
We land the ship.
As you know, Captain,
the landing procedure
requires a significant output
of energy. With shield strength
as low as it is, we can't even
be certain the ship
will survive the descent.
What's the alternative?
We're up here,
the deuterium's down there,
and we're stuck
without it.
We've come this far.
Janeway
to Engineering.
Vent all plasma
from the nacelles.
Transfer any available power
to atmospheric thrusters
and stand by
to commence landing sequence.
B'ELANNA:
Acknowledged, Captain.
Commander Chakotay,
take the com.
Tom's gonna be sorry
he missed this.
Code Blue.
( beep )
Commander Tuvok
to all hands.
Go to blue alert and report
to Code Blue stations.
Atmospheric controls
at standby.
Landing struts
online.
Inertial dampers
at maximum.
All operative decks report
Condition Blue.
Let us down easy,
Commander.
( beeping )
( dramatic theme playing )
We're on
a declining glide trajectory.
Altitude
150 kilometers.
A thermionic discharge.
Shields down
to 81 percent.
( rumbling )
Shields at 43 percent.
Chakotay.
I think we're through
the worst of it.
Almost.
Shields at 22 percent
and falling.
Can you
shore them up?
Negative.
There's no more available power.
Engaging landing struts.
Brace for impact!
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
( sighing ):
Status?
I could give you
a litany
of damaged systems,
Captain,
but suffice it to say,
now that we're down,
we won't be
going up again soon.
Start organizing
repair crews.
Well, that was very good,
Commander.
Take an away team
and find Harry and Tom.
Chakotay!
You're going out to look
for them, aren't you?
That's right.
Take me with you.
I can't do that,
B'Elanna.
You're needed here
to complete repairs.
I've already handed out
assignments.
Vorik's
on top of it.
I wanna help you find them.
Look...
I know you're concerned
about Tom and Harry.
We all are.
I'll have them back
safe and sound in no time.
Don't patronize me.
We both know how dangerous
that environment is.
They could be
in serious trouble.
You're right. I don't know
what we're going to find.
That's why I need
cool heads.
You think I can't
control myself?
I think you're a little
too close to this.
You're damn right
I am.
If someone you loved
was missing on this planet,
you would be the first one
out that door, and you know it.
B'Elanna,
the clock is ticking.
Go back to Engineering,
do your job,
and let me do mine.
Do me a favor.
What?
Take Seven of Nine
with you.
You're recommending her?
You said you needed cool heads,
didn't you?
Nobody's head is cooler
than hers.
( sighs )
All right.
And bring them back safe.
I will.
( dramatic theme playing )
( humming loudly )
( singing )
Excuse me, doctor.
Yes, Mr. Neelix?
We'd like to sleep now,
if you don't mind.
Not at all.
Make yourselves comfortable.
But you seem...
busy.
Oh, don't mind me.
Just going about
my routine.
Sleep away.
( humming )
( singing loudly )
What about
the lights?
What about them?
Could we turn
them off?
You don't expect me
to work in the dark, do you?
Well, no,
but I'll never be able
to fall asleep.
That's not my problem,
is it?
I've got a very,
very busy day tomorrow
and my next shift
is just four hours away.
Perhaps you should've
thought of that
when choosing
your accommodations.
Well,
if we can't sleep,
I guess we'll just have to find
some other way to pass the time.
How about a sing-along?
I could teach you all some
Talaxian rondos,
and I know
a Vulcan funeral dirge,
not to mention
the classics of Klingon opera.
( blurting off-key notes )
Very well,
Mr. Neelix,
you win.
Pleasant dreams.
( tranquil music playing )
Computer, lights off.
( beeping )
( dramatic theme playing )
( tricorder beeping )
( steam hissing )
You're a little jumpy,
aren't you?
I thought
I heard something.
Now you know why
they call it demon-class.
Demon implies
a presence.
This planetoid
is unoccupied.
( beeping )
I'm picking up
the shuttlecraft.
( beeping )
Nobody home.
It's unlikely
their environmental suits
were able to survive
the elements for this long.
I hope you're wrong.
( beeping continues )
( dramatic theme playing )
( steam hissing )
CHAKOTAY:
Looks like they went
this way.
My tricorder isn't picking up
any life signs.
How did you reach
that conclusion?
Footprints.
I guess you
never assimilated
any Indian scouts.
SEVEN:
High concentrations
of deuterium...
Coming from this fluid.
SEVEN:
I'll collect a sample.
Let's find
Tom and Harry first.
We'll collect
the deuterium later.
As you wish.
Maybe they found
some shelter inside.
( crashing )
Commander!
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
( grunting )
Good to see you guys.
( grunts )
Welcome to
the demon planet.
( dramatic theme swells )
( dramatic theme playing )
Our suits were corroding,
our lungs were burning,
we were suffocating!
( chuckles ):
You know what they say
about your life
passing before your eyes?
Well, it's true.
I was finally getting
past puberty
when suddenly,
I lost consciousness.
I don't know how long
I was out, but...
The next thing I knew,
I was awake,
and...
And I was
breathing normally,
and I looked
over at Harry.
He was breathing
normally too,
with his helmet off,
and-and we just looked
at each other,
heh, and we just
started laughing.
I know
it sounds crazy,
but it was
an exhilarating experience.
His vital signs
are normal.
Apparently,
he has adapted.
Just the same,
we'd better let
the doctor take
a look at you.
Chakotay
to Voyager.
I've already tried that.
The com signal
can't get out of the caves.
Then we'll call again
when we get back outside.
I'm telling you,
Chakotay,
( laughs )
it was an amazing experience.
It-it's like when you're a kid
who's afraid of the water,
and you suddenly realize
that you can swim.
Go ahead.
Take your helmets off.
Try it.
I'm glad you're
feeling all right,
but none of us should
be taking any risks
until we know exactly
what's going on.
Don't tell me that
a big, tough guy like you
is afraid of a little
poisoned atmosphere.
Where's Harry?
He's further inside
the cave.
We found a huge cache
of deuterium.
Let's find it, and get
you two back to the ship.
Whatever you say,
boss,
but I'm telling you, we could
breathe this air forever.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
Lieutenant.
Yes.
We should have
transporters
back online
within the hour.
Well, that's great,
but right now,
I'm more concerned
with little things,
like, oh,
I don't know,
say,
life support?
Indeed. According
to my calculations,
environmental systems
will cease to function
in two hours.
You say that like you're
giving me the weather report.
Well, I agree
the situation is dire,
but losing our cool
will not help matters.
Losing our cool?
Where did you pick up
that expression?
Mr. Paris.
Well, there's hope
for you yet.
Now,
how about giving me a hand?
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
CHAKOTAY:
Harry.
Commander.
Isn't it
incredible?
That's what I've been
trying to tell them.
Are you feeling okay,
Harry?
Never better. If we could get
some mobile transporters down
here, we could mine enough
deuterium to get us all
the way to the Alpha Quadrant
and back again.
Tom tells me you've already
picked up 20 kilos.
That should be enough to get
the main systems back online.
Let's get back to the ship,
have the doctor take
a look at you.
I'd rather stay here
and keep working,
if it's all the same to you.
It's not.
Heh, really, Commander,
I'm fine.
You should send some more
personnel out to help.
They won't even need
environmental suits.
I appreciate
your enthusiasm,
but we're going back
to Voyager. Now.
It's all right,
Harry.
Once the Doc takes a look at us
and sees we're fine,
we'll get right
back to work.
JANEWAY: Status, Mr. Tuvok.
TUVOK: I've shut down
life support
everywhere but Decks 1 and 5.
It should provide us with an
extra hour of breathable air.
CHAKOTAY:
Chakotay to Voyager.
Janeway here.
CHAKOTAY:
We found Tom and Harry.
First good news I've had all
day. What about the deuterium?
CHAKOTAY:
We've got a few kilos.
We're on our way back
to Voyager now.
JANEWAY:
What's your position?
CHAKOTAY:
About two kilometers
from the ship.
Captain...
Transporters are coming back on.
We should be able
to beam you back
from that distance,.
but it may take a few minutes.
Have the doctor
standing by.
I think he's gonna want to
take a look at Tom and Harry.
( dramatic theme playing )
( snoring )
( mellow theme playing )
Computer,
lights.
Maximum
illumination.
Everybody up.
Rise and shine,
Mr. Neelix.
What's going on?
It's checkout time.
It's the middle
of the night.
Medicine
knows no time clock.
I've got patients
on the way,
and there's no more
room at the inn.
Patients?
Is somebody sick?
I can't answer that until
I've examined them, now can I?
Examine who?
Ensign Kim and
Lieutenant Paris.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
Yes. You and your friends
can vacate the premises.
Right. Move!
You heard the doctor!
This is an emergency
evacuation!
Move! Move!
Move!
Doctor.
Yes.
Thanks for
your hospitality,
and if you ever need
a place to stay,
my door's always open.
( dramatic theme playing )
Energizing.
( beeping )
( Paris &amp; Kim gasping )
Beam Tom and Harry
to Sickbay.
( gasping )
( device whirs )
( coughing continues )
What happened
to them?
As soon as we beamed aboard,
they started suffocating.
Computer, erect a level-7 force
field around bio-beds 1 and 2.
COMPUTER:
Force field established.
What are you doing?
Filling the area
inside the force field
with the atmospheric gases
from the planet.
Try to breathe
normally now.
Easy,
or you'll hyperventilate.
( Paris &amp; Kim
continue gasping )
Slowly,
in and out.
In and out.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
The doctor continues
to investigate Tom and Harry
whose condition seems
as serious as it is strange.
That stuff is in
our blood?
I'm afraid so. From what I can
tell, you've been bioformed.
Bioformed?
Think of it as the opposite
of terraforming.
In the same way we adapt
the environment of a planet
to suit our needs,
this planet...
has adapted you.
How is that possible?
This fluid somehow
entered your bloodstream
and began altering
your physiology
at the cellular level.
I haven't had the time
to analyze the substance,
but I hope
to have some answers soon.
I'd like to run a few tests
of my own, if you don't mind.
Of course.
So, what's our prognosis,
doc?
Well...
you'll be fine.
As long as you keep breathing
the planet's gases.
You mean we have to stay
inside this force field?
I'm afraid
it's worse than that.
The atmosphere of this planet
can't be replicated safely.
Which means...
if we leave...
we'll have
nothing to breathe.
Exactly.
Either we find a way
to treat your condition...
...or you'll have to be
left behind.
( dramatic theme playing )
Can the bioforming
process be reversed?
As it stands,
I don't know enough about
the phenomenon to undo it.
I'll send Chakotay and Seven
back to the surface.
They'll gather as much
information as they can.
B'Elanna and I will start
running tests on this.
Let me go with
the away team, Captain.
I know the terrain.
I can help.
Doctor?
Right now, they're better off
out there than they are in here.
But one of you will
have to remain,
so I can monitor
your condition.
No problem.
I volunteer Tom to stay here
and play guinea pig.
( dramatic theme playing )
SEVEN:
Each square kilometer
of this planetoid
is less appealing
than the last.
I think
it's breathtaking.
SEVEN:
Breathtaking?
Yes.
SEVEN:
Perhaps your
recent experience
has impaired
your perceptions.
No,
I don't think so.
I wasn't really
seeing it before.
Seeing what?
The beauty.
Would you care
to point out an example?
Look over there.
What do you see?
I see monochromatic
geological formations,
dust, haze.
What do you see,
Harry?
To me,
those geological formations
are a dozen shades
of red and gold.
That dust...
it's glowing.
And the haze...
it seems to intensify
the colors.
I'm sorry.
I know it's weird, but I feel
connected to this place.
Connected how?
I'm picking up
humanoid life signs.
Location?
100 meters
this way.
JANEWAY:
Magnify, factor 10.
Deuterium,
hydrogen sulfate, dichromates.
Add a little
sodium chloride,
and it would probably taste
a lot like Neelix's soup.
We should be so lucky.
( chuckling )
Oh, what's this?
Magnify, factor 20.
( beeping )
Captain?
That's a protein molecule.
This fluid has
organic properties.
Let me see the sample that's
been treated with the reagents.
Captain...
Let's get you
to Sickbay.
Wait.
That might not be necessary.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
( tricorder beeping )
( ominous theme playing )
( repetitive beeping )
Commander!
( ominous theme swells
dramatically )
Janeway to Bridge.
Report.
A large pool
of the metallic compound
is forming
beneath the ship.
We are sinking,
Captain.
On my way.
Get down to Engineering.
Get thrusters online.
We're getting off this planet.
CHAKOTAY:
I'm not sure how,
but they're still alive.
SEVEN: Just barely.
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK: Tuvok to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
TUVOK:
The Captain has ordered
an emergency ascent.
We must bring you back
to the ship.
CHAKOTAY:
Understood.
I've got five to beam back.
Five?
We found another Paris and Kim.
I can't explain it.
I think I can.
Prepare for transport.
Beam us directly
to Sickbay.
No.
I don't wanna go back.
Transporters are still
acting up.
We can't get
individual locks.
We're gonna have to grab you
in a wide beam,
and bring you in
as a group.
Acknowledged.
I belong here.
CHAKOTAY:
Maybe so,
but until we know
what's going on,
you've got to come back
with us to the ship.
( panting )
Harry, no!
( dramatic theme playing )
Four of the away team are
in Sickbay, Captain.
I'm trying to get a lock
on the fifth.
It is Ensign Kim,
or rather,
one of the Ensigns Kim.
The ship is
continuing to sink.
Then there's no time. We've got
to get back into orbit.
We'll worry about Harry,
or whoever he is, once we're up.
Bring antigrav thrusters
online.
TUVOK:
Thrusters enabled.
Inertial dampers
to flight configuration.
Dampers reconfigured.
All stations report ready.
Initiating ascent.
I need power
to the thrusters.
We are being restrained
by an electromagnetic force.
Compensate.
No effect.
Decks 14 and 15
are submerged.
The ship is
continuing to sink.
( dramatic theme playing )
Report.
Thrusters are off-line
due to an overload.
Decks 13 through 15
are submerged.
If we don't lift off soon,
the hull will begin to corrode.
Bridge to Engineering.
Ensign Vorik
here.
JANEWAY:
I need thrusters back online.
Lieutenant Torres sent a team to
the thruster control junction.
JANEWAY: How long?
At least a half an hour.
TUVOK:
Even if thrusters
are repaired,
they won't be of much use
if we sink any deeper.
There must be some way
to disperse it.
Try a nadion burst
from the phaser emitters.
It may weaken the
electromagnetic properties
of the fluid.
Aye, Captain.
I'm on my way to Sickbay
to check on Harry and Tom.
You've got the Bridge.
How are they?
Lucky. The backup systems
in their environmental suits
kept their vital functions
going.
It'll take time,
but they'll recover.
And him?
Aside from his ability
to breathe the rarefied air
on this planet,
he's the exact duplicate
of Mr. Paris.
He even seems to share
his memories,
not to mention
his winning personality.
B'Elanna and I
discovered
that the fluid has
mimetic properties.
Somehow,
it reads the DNA
of whatever
it comes in contact with
and recreates it.
Fascinating.
Can you tell me
who you are?
Please,
just let me go back.
Not until I find out
why two of my crew
have been
duplicated.
Captain,
you have to believe me.
I don't know any more
than you do about this.
Until he showed up,
I thought I was Tom Paris.
A little changed by my
experience on the planet maybe,
but now I don't know who
or what I am.
All I know is that
I have to get off this ship
and go back down
to the surface.
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK: We're ready to try
the nadion burst, Captain.
Do it.
( weapon fires, ship rumbles )
( groans )
What are you doing?
( comlink beeps)
TUVOK: Captain,
we're receiving
an urgent hail.
It's from Ensign Kim,
the one on the surface.
Put him through.
KIM:
Captain, please!
Stop what you're doing!
If you really do have
Harry Kim's memories,
you know that I'm going to do
whatever it takes
to get this ship
back in orbit.
You can't do that!
JANEWAY:
Why not?
I... I'm not sure
I understand it myself.
Well, then you're gonna have
to help me figure it out.
Mr. Tuvok, I'm on my way
to Transporter Room 1.
Erect a level-7 force field
around the platform.
Fill it with atmosphere
from the planet
and then beam Mr. Kim,
or rather his duplicate, aboard.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
( dramatic theme playing )
Do you have
a lock on him?
WOMAN: Yes, ma'am.
Energize.
Release my vessel.
We can't do that.
We?
The planet and I,
we're connected
somehow.
I can't explain it,
Captain.
I only know
that you've got to stop.
And I'm willing
to stop,
but I'll say it again,
release the ship.
No. We need you.
Janeway to Tuvok.
Fire.
( weapon fires, ship rumbles )
( gasping )
What are you?
Stop. No.
I'll fire again.
You're killing us.
You're leaving me
no choice.
It's not fair.
It's wrong!
Janeway to Tuvok...
No!
No, no, no.
Please, no more.
Hold your fire, Tuvok.
TUVOK:
Captain, we are continuing
to submerge.
Hold your fire.
TUVOK: Acknowledged.
I want some answers.
I'm trying to understand.
This is hard for me as well.
You said you have
a connection to this planet.
You talk about it
like it's alive.
Alive?
Yes...
But not the planet.
The silver blood.
The compound that sampled
Harry's DNA...
and created you.
Yes.
But it's never been conscious,
never sentient
before now...
Before me and the other.
Tom Paris.
We're the first.
Don't you see? You came here.
You showed us.
When the compound
came in contact
with Tom and Harry,
it experienced awareness
for the first time.
Before,
it was only instinct...
Sound and light
and heat.
But those two...
showed us thought.
I'm beginning to understand.
This silver blood...
experienced sentience...
And now you want more.
You want to duplicate
the rest of this crew
and populate this planet.
You're trying so hard
to reach home, but...
this can be home.
Not for me,
and not for my people.
Do you understand
why we can't stay here?
I think so.
Well, then release us.
We'd rather die
than be alone.
We deserve life.
This silver blood
that created you...
It duplicated Harry
without killing him.
So you don't need
our bodies...
Only samples of DNA.
Release Voyager...
And I'll speak to my crew.
And if they're willing,
I'll let you duplicate
the rest of us.
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK: Bridge to Janeway.
We've stopped, Captain.
We're no longer submerging.
JANEWAY:
Understood.
We're getting out
of here, Tuvok,
but first, assemble the crew
in Cargo Bay 1,
and have the doctor
meet me there.
Captain...?
JANEWAY:
I'll explain later.
It's time to meet
your new family.
( dramatic theme playing )
All stations report
ready for liftoff.
TUVOK:
Code Blue status
confirmed.
JANEWAY:
Take us up, Mr. Paris.
Aye, Captain.
( engine rumbling )
( triumphant theme playing )