( mellow theme playing )
( people chattering
indistinctly )
Lieutenant, Ensign.
Hey, Seven.
Have some dinner.
The potato salad
isn't half bad.
I do not require
nutrition at this time.
I would like
to talk with you.
Okay.
Ensign Kim,
what is your place of origin?
You mean where am I from?
Well,
I was born in South Carolina--
Lieutenant Torres, explain
why you became a
member of the Maquis.
Um, it was through Chakotay.
I met him... Well, actually,
he saved my life--
List the sports you play.
I've dabbled in quite a few...
tennis, parrises squares...
but my favorite is volleyball.
It's--
SEVEN:
Specify the foods
you find enjoyable.
Seven, what is this?
Describe the nature
of your sexual relationship
with Lieutenant Paris.
Okay, that's it.
Computer,
freeze program.
Would you care to explain
what you're doing?
I'm doing exactly
what you instructed me to do.
I hardly think so.
I created this program
to help you become
more comfortable
in social situations,
not to practice
alienating people.
You made recommendations about
how to carry on a conversation.
That's true.
You said it's helpful if people
feel you're interested
in them.
Correct.
And that drawing them out
by asking them about
themselves is one
way to demonstrate
that interest.
That doesn't mean subjecting
them to an interrogation.
You have to let them answer.
Listen to what
they're saying.
Ask another question
on the same subject.
Take your time.
Shall we try again?
I believe I am overdue
for my weekly
medical maintenance.
We should go.
Seven, you've never volunteered
for a checkup before.
It is preferable
to remaining here.
( dramatic theme playing )
What have we got here?
Looks like a
Mutara-class nebula
with a few trace
constituents
that aren't in
our database,
but they're showing up
in minute quantities.
The nebula is vast,
Captain.
It extends beyond the reach
of our sensors.
Huh. Then I guess we
won't try to go around it.
Tom, take us in
at one-half impulse.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm detecting a slight
radioactive field.
It's...
( gasping )
Harry?
Nothing. Uh...
it's just a headache coming on.
( winces )
Maybe you should
go to Sickbay.
Yeah, maybe so.
( grunts )
Captain!
( groans )
( moans )
( groaning )
Oh, God!
( both groaning )
Oh...
( moans )
( triumphant theme playing )
( gasping )
Tom, turn us around.
Get us out of here.
( groaning )
Janeway to Sickbay.
DOCTOR: Yes, Captain.
We need help.
What happened?
I'm being inundated with calls!
JANEWAY: Hurry!
Seven, go to the Bridge.
Use the dermal regenerator
to treat the burns.
( gasping )
( groaning )
( moaning )
( beeping )
Course laid in.
( moaning )
( panting )
We've cleared the nebula.
( moans )
( sighs )
All stop.
He's dead.
( sighs )
The nebula extends for at least
110 light-years, possibly more.
JANEWAY:
At the least it
would take us
well over a month
to get through it
and more than a year
to get around it.
The crew was unable
to tolerate the nebula
for even a few minutes.
They certainly could not
survive a month.
We've come
15,000 light-years.
We haven't been stopped
by temporal anomalies,
warp-core breaches
or hostile aliens,
and I am damned
if I'm going
to be stopped
by a nebula.
I'll be in Sickbay.
I've analyzed a sample of
the gases from the nebula.
I think the damage came
from subnucleonic radiation.
Even the briefest exposure
is devastating
to organic tissue.
Can you give us any protection
against the effects?
Yes.
Stasis chambers.
Independent life support
for each unit.
Are you suggesting...
that the entire crew
be put in suspended
animation?
Yes.
I, of course,
would stay on line
in order to monitor everyone.
Well, this is
a drastic step, doctor.
Are there
any other options?
Adjusting the shields,
inoculations?
I assure you, I've considered
all possibilities.
This is the only way.
There's more to getting
through the nebula
than monitoring the crew.
Who would regulate ship systems,
make course adjustments?
I think I've demonstrated
that I have a command
of the rudimentary aspects
of piloting.
Of course you have,
and I know that you could do it,
but you'll need backup.
We have no idea what
effect the nebula radiation
might have on your holo-matrix.
What if you went off-line?
There was only one
crew member besides myself
that seemed unaffected
by the nebula.
JANEWAY:
I want you to understand
the seriousness
of this responsibility.
The lives of the entire crew
will be on your shoulders.
You doubt my ability
to fulfill this task.
Ordinarily, not at all,
but this is
an unusual situation.
After being in the collective...
...it wasn't easy for you
to adjust to a ship
with only 150 people on it,
was it, Seven?
How would you feel
with only the doctor
for company?
I will adapt.
Most humans don't react
particularly well
to long periods
of isolation.
Borg drones have
even more difficulty.
As you pointed out,
I am neither human nor Borg.
I can do this, Captain.
All right.
I'll work with
my senior staff
to draw up a list of duties,
but let me make it clear.
The doctor will be
in command.
You will follow
his instructions
just as you would
follow mine.
Follow the orders
of a hologram.
He's our Chief Medical Officer,
and he is thoroughly grounded
in Starfleet protocols.
You will report to him.
I understand.
( dramatic theme playing )
The doctor's preparing
the stasis units now.
They should be ready
by 1700 hours.
And...
how long
will this be for?
We don't know for certain.
At least a month,
maybe longer if the nebula
is larger than we estimate.
I've never been
in long-term stasis.
Are there
any side effects?
The doctor assures me
it'll be just like taking a nap.
We'll go into the units,
our cardiopulmonary systems
will be slowed,
neural activity suspended,
and we'll wake up feeling
as though we'd had
a good night's sleep.
There are things
that can go wrong.
At least,
that's what I've read.
JANEWAY:
We will be carefully
monitored by Seven
and the doctor,
who will check our vital signs
four times a day
and take care of any
other problems.
( nervous laugh )
I assume that we've explored
all the alternatives.
I think we're all feeling
uneasy about this,
and I'd be lying if I said
I don't have concerns myself,
and I think it's about
loss of control.
We always feel better
if we think we're in charge
of our own circumstances.
In stasis,
we're giving up that control,
and no Starfleet officer
likes to do that.
But crews have been in stasis
much longer than a month.
I think we can handle this.
All right?
You're free
until 1700 hours.
I'll make a shipwide
announcement
when the doctor's ready.
Dismissed.
( door opens )
Something else?
( door closes )
I want you to tell me
that this isn't a mistake.
Your turn to get
reassurance?
Maybe.
But my concern
isn't about going into stasis.
It's about who you're
leaving in charge.
You're worried about Seven.
Maybe you need to step outside
yourself for a minute.
Look at the fact
that here's someone
who's butted horns with you
from the moment
she came on board...
who disregards authority
and actively disobeys orders
when she doesn't agree
with them.
And this is the person
I'm giving responsibility
for the lives of
this entire crew.
I suppose you want me
to tell you I'm not crazy.
In a nutshell.
( sighs )
I know your bond
with Seven is unique,
different from everyone else's.
From the beginning,
you've seen things in her
that no one else could.
But maybe you
could help me understand
some of those things.
I don't know if I can.
It's just instinct.
There's something
inside me that says
she can be redeemed.
In spite of her
insolent attitude,
I honestly believe she
wants to do well by us.
( sighs )
That's good enough for me.
See you at 1700 hours.
( dramatic theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
If I have to take
a nap for a month,
I really would rather do it
in my quarters.
Everyone's being relocated
here to Deck 14,
so we can monitor you
more easily.
Hop in.
Come on, Tom.
Sleepy time.
What if we...
had to get out in a hurry?
You can unlock the unit
from inside, Tom.
DOCTOR:
Do I detect a hint
of claustrophobia,
Lieutenant?
[EXHALES]
Why do they have to design
these things like coffins?
Should we replicate you
a teddy bear?
Sleep tight.
( keypad beeping )
( whooshing )
Have no worries, Captain.
You'll go to sleep,
and the next thing you know,
I'll be standing over you,
telling you
we're through the nebula.
I'm leaving this ship
in good hands.
I have every confidence
in both of you.
See you in a month.
( dramatic theme playing )
( sighs )
( keypad beeping )
( whooshing )
Well,
it's just the two of us now.
SEVEN:
Personal Log, Seven of Nine,
Stardate 51929.3.
This is the tenth day
of our journey
through the Mutara nebula.
I have created
an efficient daily routine.
Nutritional supplement
fourteen-beta-seven.
( beeping )
( tranquil theme playing )
( sighs )
( consoles beeping )
( door opens )
( console beeping )
Computer, adjust heading
by .347 degrees starboard.
COMPUTER:
Course adjusted.
Seven of Nine to the doctor.
Go ahead.
Lieutenant Paris
has left his stasis unit
and is unconscious.
DOCTOR:
I'll be right there.
Apparently, he's more
claustrophobic than I thought.
But he doesn't seem to have
suffered any ill effects.
Is this likely
to happen again?
It's not unheard of
for people to come
out of stasis
and start wandering.
Leave it to
Mr. Paris to be
just as much trouble now
as when he's awake.
( beeping )
You knew this might happen.
Why complain about it?
If you had even the slightest
sense of humor,
you'd realize
I was making a small joke.
Very small.
Give me his vital signs.
Please.
Pulse, 42.
Body temperature 97.6.
Blood pressure 100 over 50.
Good.
I will continue
on my rounds.
I think not.
We're paying a visit
to the holodeck.
I have no time
for frivolous pursuits.
This isn't frivolous.
It's essential.
You've been getting more
irritable and short-tempered
with each passing day.
So have you.
That's only because
I'm having to put up with you.
I think you need
a little brush-up course
in how to get along
with people.
There is no one here
to get along with.
I'm here.
This isn't a suggestion,
and it's not a request.
It's an order.
( sighs )
Try one, Commander.
Thank you, Neelix.
Captain?
Oh, thank you.
What have we here?
Delicious.
Join the party, Seven.
It's no fun to stand
there by yourself.
I have no desire
to have fun.
No?
I'm attempting to recalibrate
the warp field, in order to
resist the nebula's radiation.
I understand you have some
knowledge of warp field theory.
Perhaps you could assist me.
I'd be happy
to give it a try.
Let's see...
the subspace field matrix
looks right...
Captain?
Excuse me a minute.
Perhaps you could help,
as well.
We're attempting
to find
a stronger warp field
calibration.
How interesting.
Maybe if we vary
the EM stress parameters,
the warp field
dynamic would increase.
Excellent idea, Captain.
And if the warp coils
were re-phased,
it would increase power
to the nacelles.
There is an
additional problem.
We must compensate
for a subspace induction
drag on the engines.
Pardon me, Captain,
Mr. Neelix.
Computer,
freeze program.
You're completely missing
the point of this exercise.
You're supposed to be
mixing and mingling,
not working on
engineering problems.
You ordered me to participate
in this program.
You did not specify topics
of conversation.
You're splitting hairs.
You know very well
what purpose
this program is
supposed to serve.
I find that it serves
no purpose whatsoever.
Because you're being
intentionally perverse.
Holodecks are
a pointless endeavor,
fulfilling some human need
to fantasize.
I have no such need.
What you need is
some editorial skill
in your self-expression.
Between impulse and action,
there is a realm of good taste
begging for
your acquaintance.
I find your
self-expression ponderous.
And I can't put up with this
for another month.
We can arrange
to avoid one another.
I wish it were that simple.
Unfortunately,
you have to report to me
four times a day, to keep me
informed about the crew.
We can minimize those reports.
COMPUTER: Warning.
( beeping )
Emergency procedures in effect.
Computer, what is the nature
of the emergency?
COMPUTER:
The antimatter storage tanks
are failing.
( alarm sounding )
A cascade effect
is in progress.
The warp field coils
are compromised,
primary deuterium tank
is rupturing,
and the plasma conduits
are ready to breach.
This is awful.
We have to eject
the antimatter tanks.
We've got to coordinate
the effort.
You go to Engineering.
I'll go to the Bridge.
Doctor to Seven.
Yes, doctor.
It's worse than we thought.
Engineering is flooded with
plasma. You'll never get in.
I believe I can survive long
enough to eject the assembly.
DOCTOR:
It's too late!
Sensors show
plasma conduits rupturing
on Decks Seven and Thirteen.
I can do it.
( alarm beeping )
Seven! There's been another
plasma discharge in Engineering!
The hull is breaching.
Get out!
( door opening )
DOCTOR:
Seven, do you hear me?
It's all right, doctor.
False alarm.
( dramatic theme playing )
DOCTOR:
Look here.
I think I've found
the problem.
There are malfunctions
in a number of neural gel packs.
As a result, false readings
were fed to the sensors,
which detected an emergency
when there was none.
We must repair them.
They seem to be
in sequence six-theta-nine.
We'll need replacement packs
and a repair--
Repair kit.
( door opens )
These tubes certainly
weren't designed
with creature comfort
in mind.
It seems to me the shipbuilders
should've created a space
in which one
could walk upright.
But they did not.
It doesn't help to
complain about it now.
I'll complain if I want to.
It's comforting.
We can access sequence
six-theta-nine
from this junction.
( beeping )
Odd.
I've never seen this kind
of neural activity
in the gel packs.
In what sense?
The neurodes are discharging
in random bursts.
I would imagine the nebular
activity is causing it.
I'll take this back
to Sickbay for further study.
I will reroute
the command processors
to bypass this series.
( sighs )
This journey certainly
hasn't lacked excitement.
I can't complain
about being bored.
Since you find it comforting,
you'll undoubtedly
find something else
to complain about.
No doubt.
You really should try it.
What's happening?
My... My program is degrading.
The mobile emitter?
I don't know.
I have to get back to Sickbay.
Hurry!
I am hurrying.
If the mobile emitter goes
off-line while I'm out of
Sickbay, my program
may be irretrievable!
Don't panic.
It's counterproductive.
That's easy for you to say.
You're not facing
cybernetic oblivion.
( dramatic theme playing )
Doctor...
If that happens again,
I'm a goner.
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
( sighs )
Home, sweet Sickbay.
I never thought
I'd be so glad
to see these walls.
Give me the emitter.
The electro-optic
modulator is damaged.
You're right.
It's worthless.
There's no way I can risk using
it now. I'm stuck here.
The nebula is having
a deleterious effect
on all the ship's technology.
And we still have
weeks to go.
It's up to you to keep
the ship running.
We can't afford to break down
in this nebula.
( sighs )
I won't disappoint you.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
COMPUTER: 0600 hours.
Regeneration sequence
complete.
( sighs )
Personal Log, Seven of Nine,
Stardate 51932.4.
The 29th day
in the Mutara nebula.
I believe I am beginning
to feel the effects
of this prolonged isolation.
My dreams have been...
disturbing...
...but I am determined to
fulfill my responsibilities.
With the doctor confined
to Sickbay,
I have taken on
increasing duties.
The ship's systems
are beginning to require
constant maintenance
in order to avert disaster.
This morning, I must purge
the auxiliary plasma vents.
End log.
( beeping )
Computer, trim heading
by .31 degrees port.
Computer, respond.
Computer, trim heading
by .31 degrees port.
( beeping )
COMPUTER ( distorted ):
Attempting to make correction.
Please stand by.
( beeping continues )
Attempting to make correction.
Unable to comply.
Manual override.
Computer, initiate
a level-four diagnostic
of your command processors.
COMPUTER ( distorted ):
Diagnostic in progress.
Astrometrics.
COMPUTER:
Diagnostic complete.
Analyze.
COMPUTER:
Quantum failures are present in
33 percent of gel pack relays.
Reroute all functional relays
through subprocessor
chi-one-four.
COMPUTER ( no distortion ):
Rerouting complete.
Relay failures bypassed.
Display Voyager's current
position within the nebula.
How long to complete passage
through the nebula?
COMPUTER:
Six days, five hours.
Six days.
( beeping )
PARIS:
Seven...
Help!
( ominous theme playing )
( door opens )
COMPUTER:
Proximity alert.
Vessel approaching.
The vessel is hailing.
Open a channel.
COMPUTER:
Channel open.
This is the
Federation Starship Voyager.
State your identity.
ALIEN:
I'm Trajis Lo-Tarik.
I'm in need
of a microfusion chamber.
Would you consider a trade?
Why are you in this nebula?
TRAJIS:
Trying to get through it,
as I imagine you are.
Do you have liquid helium?
TRAJIS:
You're fortunate.
I have an ample supply.
I'll beam you directly
to our cargo bay.
Seven of Nine...
that's an unusual name.
How did you get it?
It was my Borg
designation.
Borg?
Never heard of them.
Are you alone
on this ship?
No. The entire crew
is here in stasis
and our doctor is in Sickbay.
I'm both pilot
and crew on my ship.
Fortunately,
I happen to be resistant
to the effects
of the nebula.
What about your technology?
The radiation is causing
damage to ours.
I've had to rebuild
my engines twice already.
If you've been in
the nebula for three weeks,
you're doing well.
I am hopeful
our propulsion system
will remain operational
for the next six days.
I'll admit I was surprised
to find another ship
headed toward me.
No one has ever managed
to cross the nebula.
If it weren't necessary,
we wouldn't be
attempting it.
I'm here by choice.
I'm determined
to be the first
to get through.
I've tried five times
before and failed,
but this time
I'm sure I'll make it.
I want to see
what's on the other side.
It is nothing remarkable.
But I'll be the first
of my kind to see it.
Tell me,
how are you handling
the loneliness?
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
No matter what you say...
you're all alone here.
The microfusion chamber
you requested.
I've heard the drones
can't stand being alone.
They're too used
to the collective.
How could you know that?
It's true, isn't it?
You said you'd never
heard of the Borg.
Don't be offended.
I've no grudge with them.
You have what you
asked for, now leave.
I thought we could keep
each other company for awhile,
maybe have
something to eat.
No.
And if I want to stay longer?
You will not
be accommodated.
( dramatic theme playing )
There's no need for this,
you know.
I mean you no harm.
I think maybe you're
a little paranoid.
That's what loneliness
can do to you.
You'd be a lot better off
to spend some time with me.
We could get to know
each other.
Quiet.
PARIS:
Seven!
Help me!
( gasping )
Seven!
( dramatic theme playing )
Seven of Nine to the doctor.
We have an intruder on board.
( beeping )
He must have
a cloaking device.
Sensors show
no alien life signs
and no evidence of a ship.
I've been working on
my mobile emitter.
I think I'm making progress,
but I still can't
leave Sickbay.
You'll have to try
to track him down.
Arm yourself,
and use extreme caution.
COMPUTER ( distorted):
Warning.
Deuterium tank levels
are fluctuating beyond
acceptable tolerances.
The computer sounds
like it needs a stimulant.
It has been experiencing
relay failures.
I have not been performing
my maintenance duties.
Do what you have to,
but keep an eye out
for the alien.
We have to assume
he's up to no good.
Seven...
are you...frightened?
I am Borg.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( banging )
Who's there?
TRAJIS:
Seven.
Help me.
NEELIX:
I'm dying, Seven.
Don't let me die.
JANEWAY ( whispering ):
The lives of the crew are on
your shoulders.
PARIS:
Seven, help me.
( eerie moaning )
KIM:
Help, Seven. I need help.
CHAKOTAY:
We need you, Seven.
( crew voices clamoring )
NEELIX:
I'm dying, Seven.
( clamoring continues )
( clamoring stops )
( beeping )
( comm beeps )
TRAJIS: Seven of Nine.
That's an unusual name.
How did you get it?
Don't want to answer me?
That's all right.
I don't mind.
I know you're
not yourself today.
But you might be interested
in what I'm doing now.
I know your sensors
can't detect me,
so if you want to know where
I am, you'll have to ask.
Playing stubborn?
That's a mistake.
It could lead to
an unfortunate accident.
Just to prove I'm willing
to give you a fair chance,
I'll ask you: What would happen
if the structural integrity
around the warp coils
collapsed?
You wouldn't have much time
to keep them from rupturing.
( suspenseful theme playing )
TRAJIS:
I couldn't bring myself
to destroy your ship.
I hope you're not
afraid of the dark.
Where are you?
TRAJIS:
Finally.
I'm glad you're responding.
It's going to be
much more interesting
if we play this game together.
Your location.
TRAJIS:
A long way from you,
on the Bridge.
Command center of your ship,
I believe.
I can do just about anything
from here.
PARIS:
Seven! Help!
( dramatic theme playing )
( gasps )
Seven to Trajis.
Are you still there?
TRAJIS:
Of course.
Do you think I'd leave now?
I am enjoying this game.
What's next?
TRAJIS:
That's better.
Well, let's just imagine
that one of the photon
torpedoes was activated
but not ejected.
I would have to get
to the torpedo bay quickly.
TRAJIS:
And even then,
you might be too late,
but, of course,
you have to try.
Let's play another game.
Let's imagine
that the oxygen on the Bridge
has been depleted.
TRAJIS: What?
What do you suppose
the results might be?
( Trajis gasping )
Computer, seal the Bridge
with a level-3 force field.
COMPUTER:
Bridge sealed.
( exhales )
Seven of Nine to the doctor.
I'm here.
SEVEN:
I have incapacitated
the alien.
He will not trouble us again.
Good work. I have my mobile
emitter back on line.
Where are you now?
In Engineering.
DOCTOR:
I'll be right there.
I have interesting news
about the neural gel packs.
Acknowledged.
( door opening )
In your heart,
you knew you'd see me again.
You can't defeat me.
You're too weak.
Don't come any closer.
You couldn't stand being alone,
could you?
You felt vulnerable, afraid,
because you know
what you are.
Stop.
At first, you thought
you could become human,
but now you know
that's impossible, don't you?
You're Borg.
That's what you're meant
to be...one of many.
But your days
of power are gone.
You're all alone now...
weak, pathetic.
Don't come any closer.
I'll kill you.
Seven?
Be careful, doctor!
He's dangerous!
Who are you talking to?
Where did he go?
There's no one else here.
He was.
He was right here.
Seven...
you're hallucinating.
No, I saw him!
There was no one else
in this room.
( sighs )
You mean I imagined him.
Yes.
I heard Lieutenant Paris
call for help.
I saw him and the others.
Did I imagine them, as well?
I believe so.
When I studied the gel pack,
I discovered the radiation
was producing a degradation
in the synaptic relays.
I'm guessing there's been
a similar effect
on your Borg implants.
The radiation
could be altering
the neurotransmitter levels
in your sensory nodes.
That would explain why
you're hearing voices...
seeing images.
But they seemed real.
Hallucinations
usually are.
That's what makes them
so frightening.
Once, when I was a drone...
I was separated from
the collective for two hours.
I experienced panic...
and apprehension.
I am feeling that way now.
I'll do everything
I can to help you.
We'll get you to Sickbay.
An anti-psychotic may help,
at least until I determine
just what neural functions
are being affected.
( explosion )
SEVEN: What was that?
COMPUTER:
Warning.
( distorting, slowing ):
Primary EPS conduits
are overloading.
I tied my mobile emitter
into the EPS conduits.
Computer,
access the EPS conduits.
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
My program's
going off-line.
No!
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Primary EPS conduits
overloading.
Secondary systems are failing.
Seven,
you've got to hang on.
Repair the EPS conduits.
Everything depends
on you now.
I cannot function alone.
You have to.
You're the only way
we can survive.
No!
( dramatic theme playing )
Display Voyager's current
position within the nebula.
KIM:
It doesn't matter.
You won't make it.
Computer, how long before
Voyager is out of the nebula?
COMPUTER ( distorted ):
Seventeen hours,
11 minutes.
That's an eternity.
Go away.
You can try to shut me out,
but it won't work.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Propulsion system failure
in progress.
( eerie moaning and gasping )
BORG DRONE:
Seven of Nine,
Tertiary Adjunct
of Unimatrix Zero One.
You have left the collective.
It was a foolish decision.
Now you are alone.
You have lost the many.
You are only one.
You have become human, weak,
pathetic.
Humans do not have
our strength.
They are imperfect.
Now you are imperfect
as well.
No.
You will not survive.
You cannot survive
without the collective.
I will adapt.
By becoming weaker,
less perfect.
I will adapt
as an individual.
One. One alone.
A Borg cannot be one.
I will become stronger.
She will die
as one...
weak, detached, isolated.
One Borg cannot survive.
I am an individual.
I will survive alone.
No. You are weak.
You will die
alone.
( sighs )
He's right.
You're in pain, Seven.
I can help you.
Bridge.
You don't have to beg me.
You don't even have to ask.
All you have to do
is make a choice.
I can survive alone.
That's where
you belong.
No.
End your pain.
Just walk through
that door,
and you'll never
be alone again.
It's not real.
COLLECTIVE:
Seven of Nine,
resistance is futile.
Bridge!
( panting )
JANEWAY:
Seven of Nine.
You look a little
worse for wear.
KIM:
I didn't know she
was still on board.
I never wanted her here
in the first place.
She won't
be here long.
She can't survive alone.
PARIS:
I'm taking bets on
how long she'll last.
She'll fall apart
before we leave the nebula.
And then everybody
will die.
Well, blame me.
I put my trust in her.
I should've known better.
COMPUTER ( distorted):
Warning. Propulsion system
failure in progress.
TUVOK:
What is she doing now?
CHAKOTAY:
She's trying to keep
the engines on line.
Place your bets.
Anybody think she can do it?
I'll lay odds
she can't.
Computer, how long until
the ship is out of the nebula?
COMPUTER:
Forty-one minutes.
Too long.
She won't make it.
That's an eternity.
Computer, reroute
available power from weapons,
sensors and environmental
controls to the engines.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Propulsion system
failure in progress.
Reroute all available power
to the engines.
COMPUTER:
Propulsion systems have failed.
All engines are off-line.
KIM:
She's got herself
a real problem now.
CHAKOTAY:
I'll say.
She's taken power
from every available system,
and it's still not enough.
If she fails
to get the ship moving,
everyone on board will die.
PARIS:
What do you think she'll do?
I know. She's thinking
if she could take power
from the stasis units
on Deck 14,
she might be able
to get those engines
back on line.
But that would mean sacrificing
some of the crew.
I don't think that would
bother her too much.
What matters to Seven
is efficiency.
Sacrificing a few
to save many
would be
an efficient plan.
She's already killed millions,
would a few more matter?
Computer, divert power from
stasis units one through 10,
and reroute to
the propulsion systems.
COMPUTER ( distorted ):
Engines are back on line.
Resume course.
KIM:
Look at that.
She did it!
But those people
she disconnected
are going to die.
I win. I knew she
didn't care about them.
( gasps )
Come to watch them die?
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Power to stasis units
has failed.
Computer, how long to complete
passage through the nebula?
COMPUTER:
Eleven minutes.
They won't last that long.
What do you do now,
Seven?
It's all up to you.
Computer, cut life support
to all decks
and reroute available power
to the stasis units.
That will keep them alive,
but what about you?
No oxygen,
no heat.
Goodbye, Seven.
( panting )
I am Seven of Nine.
I am alone...
but I will adapt.
I will...
She's coming to.
DOCTOR:
Not so fast.
Get your bearings
first.
The crew?
We came through
the nebula
in fine shape,
thanks to you.
You were the one
we almost lost.
When the ship
cleared the nebula,
the doctor came back on line
and found you unconscious.
He reinitiated life support
and woke the crew.
He tells us you've had
quite an adventure.
It was...
...interesting.
Well, when you're rested,
I'd like to hear about it.
I'm proud of you,
Seven.
You performed admirably.
I am glad
I was able to help.
KIM:
Neelix, this soup is great.
What is it?
It's my
secret recipe.
I've never told anyone
what's in it.
PARIS:
Why does that make me nervous?
Oh, come on, Tom.
Where's your sense of adventure?
PARIS:
Not in my stomach.
Food and mystery
don't go together.
I like to know
what I'm eating.
Coward.
Lieutenants Paris and Torres,
Ensign Kim.
Seven. I'm surprised
to see you here.
May I join you?
Sure. Have a seat.
Have some soup.
It's actually edible.
I don't require nourishment
at this time.
I...
felt the need
for companionship.
Well, after a month
with only the doc
for company,
I can understand it.
Yeah. Uh, what was
that like, anyway?
Just the two of you?
The doctor was very helpful.
I cannot fault him.
Well, we owe you one.
PARIS:
Yeah.
Just think,
we could've died
in those coffins.
SEVEN:
I suspect you would've found a
way out before that, Lieutenant.
What do you mean?
Lieutenant Paris refused
to stay confined.
On four separate occasions,
the doctor and I
had to put him back
into his stasis unit.
Were you, um, locked
in dark closets
or something as a child?
I just don't like
closed places.
I never have.
I don't know why.
Perhaps you dislike
being alone.
( dramatic theme playing )
( triumphant theme playing )