( grunts )
COMPUTER:
Full impact.
Final round to Janeway.
Winner, Janeway.
Good game.
For you.
Oh, come on,
Seven.
You won four out
of 10 rounds.
Nothing to be
ashamed of.
On the contrary.
I have superior
visual acuity and stamina.
I should've won
every round.
Well, Velocity is more than
a test of stamina.
It's a game of wits.
You are a
frustrating opponent.
During the final round after
you dropped your phaser,
you did not even look
at the disk.
And yet you were able
to acquire the target.
Intuition.
Intuition is
a human fallacy,
the belief that you can
predict random events.
Oh, belief had nothing
to do with it.
At some level,
conscious or otherwise,
I was aware of
several factors.
The trajectory of the disk
after I hit the wall,
the sound it made
on its return,
and the shadow it cast
on the hologrid.
Intriguing,
but implausible.
I won, didn't I?
Thanks for the match.
I wish to play again.
Not today.
You are fatigued
and concerned
that I will
defeat you.
Tired, yes.
Concerned, no.
Computer,
begin first round.
Belay that command.
Seven,
try to be a sport.
Game's over.
( dramatic theme playing )
( triumphant theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log,
stardate 51978.2.
It's been five months
since we received
the encoded message
from the Alpha Quadrant.
We know that the transmission
was from Starfleet Command,
but we still
can't decrypt it.
B'Elanna thinks
it's a lost cause,
that too much
of the datastream
has been destroyed,
but I haven't given up.
I keep hoping inspiration
will strike...somehow.
( sighs )
Good morning.
What time is it?
0500.
Oh! Well, then,
good morning.
I just heard
from Tom and Neelix.
They're about to leave
the trading colony.
Any luck?
According to Tom, the shuttle's
so loaded down with supplies
he won't make
half impulse.
Neelix is
asking permission
to bring one of
the locals on board.
He's been very helpful,
and Neelix wants to repay him
by giving him passage
to the next system.
Permission granted.
You might want
to grab some sleep.
We've got
a big day ahead.
I will in a while.
Still hunting
for buried treasure.
We've found the treasure.
I just can't pick the lock.
I've tried over
50 decryption algorithms.
Every time I piece together
a data block,
10 more come unraveled.
What did Starfleet
send us?
A map?
The location of a wormhole?
If I could decode this today,
Chakotay,
we could be home tomorrow.
Then again, it could be
Admiral Chapman's recipe
for the perfect pound cake.
I've been pinning
our hopes on this message,
but I'm starting
to wonder.
One way or another,
we've got to find out.
I'll talk to
B'Elanna.
You could enlist
Seven of Nine.
Hm...
She should have a few Borg
algorithms up her sleeve...
If she's in the mood.
Problems?
I don't know if she's restless
or if it's just me,
but we're butting heads
more than usual lately.
She seems to challenge
everything I say.
( sighing )
She's learned a lot from you
over the last year.
Maybe the pupil thinks
she's outgrowing the mentor.
Maybe.
Well, this mentor would like
another cup of coffee.
Will you join me?
Love to.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
This goes
to Engineering...
Sickbay...
Storage.
I hope that's not going
to the mess hall.
I don't remember what this is.
Neelix!
Captain,
this man is a genius.
I was trying to negotiate
with a xenon-based life-form
when the universal translator
went off-line.
Arturis here stepped in
and acted as
a perfect go-between,
and he'd never heard
either of our languages.
Oh,
they were simple.
Oh!
No insult intended.
PARIS: Neelix!
On my way.
If you two
will excuse me.
Well,
welcome to Voyager.
We may be a linguistically
simple folk,
but we're happy
to give you a ride.
Let's see if we can find you
some quarters.
Neelix was right.
Voyager is
a welcoming place.
Well,
we do our best.
( chuckles )
I can't say I've ever met
a living universal translator.
Oh, my people have
a way with languages.
I myself know
over 4,000.
And to think I still struggle
with basic Klingon.
You couldn't have heard Neelix
say more than a few phrases.
It was
all I needed.
It was enough to grasp
the grammar and syntax.
Impressive.
Oh, not really.
It's a natural ability.
Some species are born with
great physical prowess,
others, like yours,
with a generosity of spirit.
My people
can see patterns
where others see
only confusion.
Is something wrong?
No.
Tell me...
How are you at
computational languages?
Algorithms?
Trinary syntax?
It's all the same
to me.
I was wondering if you might
do us another favor.
ARTURIS:
You weren't exaggerating,
Captain.
This datastream
is badly damaged.
I'd like to see the entire
transmission again.
( beeping )
Are you...
Borg?
Yes.
You're much more
attractive
than
the average drone.
I am no longer part
of the collective.
Ah! I see,
I see.
I think I see
the problem.
Well,
may I?
Please.
( beeping )
Have you encountered
his people before?
Species 116.
Is that what
you call us?
SEVEN:
Yes. The Borg has never
been able to
assimilate them.
Not yet.
Seven...
Oh, it's all right,
Captain.
The Borg collective
is like a force of nature.
You don't feel anger
toward a storm on the horizon.
You just avoid it.
Ah.
Here it is.
It's a simple matter
of extracting
the iconometric elements
and triaxilating
a recursion matrix.
Now, why didn't I
think of that?
There's a great deal of
information here, Captain.
I think it might be useful
to utilize the other monitors.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
JANEWAY:
You've done it.
Almost. I've reconstructed over
68 kiloquads of information,
but a lot of it
is still garbled.
JANEWAY:
What about that data block,
14-beta?
That part of the message
is too degraded
to recover.
Captain, I've found
a spatial grid.
JANEWAY:
They've marked a set
of coordinates.
It's less than 10
light years from here.
Maybe Starfleet wants us
to proceed to that location.
Maybe. There's only
one way to find out.
We're approaching
the coordinates.
Take us out of warp.
Scan the vicinity.
( beeping )
I am picking up a vessel.
JANEWAY:
On-screen.
Identify.
Unless I am mistaken,
Captain,
the warp signature
is Starfleet.
( dramatic theme playing )
I'll be damned.
They came through.
Tuvok?
TUVOK:
Hailing them.
No response.
Life signs?
There is no organic matter
of any kind.
No sign of damage
to the outer hull.
KIM:
Primary systems
are online,
including life support.
Something must have
happened to the crew.
The answer is somewhere
in that Starfleet transmission.
We need to finish
decoding it.
May I call on
your talents again?
Of course.
Take an away team.
Secure the vessel.
Tom, Tuvok.
( door opens, closes )
Captain, I won't pretend
to know you well,
but I am surprised
you're not more...
encouraged by
this discovery.
I've learned to walk the line
between hope and caution.
We've had other opportunities
that didn't work out.
But I will admit,
I'm leaning toward
hope this time.
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
( beeping )
Wow.
Wow, indeed.
( beeping )
I've never seen this kind
of hull geometry.
Looks like they're taking
a whole new approach
to starship design.
TUVOK:
The USS Dauntless.
Registry: NX01-A.
Launch date: 51472.
60,000 light years
in three months.
TUVOK:
I'm trying to access
the crew logs,
but there are none.
I don't think
there was a crew.
This helm was set
for auto-navigation
to these coordinates.
It appears that Starfleet
has provided us with a new ship.
Let's not pack our bags
just yet.
I'd still like to know
how they...
( rumbling )
I'm reading power fluctuations
in the warp core,
if you can call it
a warp core.
I don't recognize
this engine configuration.
( rumbling )
Let's go take a look.
PARIS:
I think we've found
our engine core.
Some kind of
new warp drive?
It's not antimatter.
It's...
I don't know what
it is.
( rumbling )
( beeping )
They call this thing a
"quantum slipstream drive."
Quantum slipstream?
I've never seen that
in the engineering manuals.
( console beeping )
The ship's
powering up.
Auto-navigation
is kicking in.
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
Bridge to Janeway.
The vessel's moving away
at high impulse.
KIM:
I can't raise the away team.
Pursuit course,
Ensign.
( door opens, closes )
( beeping )
I can't shut down
the drive!
Computer,
disable propulsion!
COMPUTER:
Unable to comply.
Hang on!
( dramatic theme playing )
Bridge to Janeway.
They're gone.
Look at this.
Energy from the quantum drive
is being routed through
the main deflector.
Is that what's creating
the slipstream?
It looks that way.
Fascinating.
Can you make it stop?
I'll try accessing
helm controls.
We're back
in normal space.
Scan for Voyager.
No sign of them.
Commander...
We've traveled
over 15 light years.
( dramatic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
After two days
at high warp,
we've rendezvoused with
the Dauntless.
Arturis has helped us
reconstruct most of
the Starfleet message.
The pieces of this puzzle
are finally coming together.
Slipstream technology
is experimental and high risk,
but it's come a long way
in the past year.
We've conducted 47 trial runs,
all of them successful,
but each flight lasted
only five days.
In order to reach Earth,
you'd have to remain
at slipstream velocity
for a full three months.
Can your crew
survive that long?
We believe they can,
and we encourage you to try.
Everything you'll need
is on the Dauntless:
power cells, supplies,
living quarters.
Safe journey.
We hope to see you soon.
( dramatic theme playing )
Admiral Hayes.
Good man.
Fine officer.
Bit of a windbag.
( chuckling )
Let's talk about the risk.
Doctor?
I've examined the away team
for signs of cell damage
or physiological stress.
Nothing.
Their little joyride didn't
harm them in the slightest.
Long-term effects?
I'm running the medical
projections right now.
So far,
the results are encouraging.
And the Dauntless
itself?
I'd say it's in pretty
good shape, considering.
B'ELANNA:
I've been looking over
the primary systems,
helm, ops, tactical.
They're comparable
to Voyager's,
but it's a lean ship,
Captain.
No shuttlecraft,
only one transporter,
no holodecks,
no replicators...
Well, Mr. Neelix, you may have
your work cut out for you.
Ready and willing,
Captain.
So, what are we
waiting for?
Your enthusiasm
is premature.
Voyager is
a proven vessel.
It would be reckless
to abandon it
so quickly.
KIM: Come on,
where's that Borg spirit?
We'll adapt.
My Borg spirit gives me
an objectivity you lack.
She has a point.
This would mean leaving
Voyager behind.
Is there any way we could modify
Voyager to create
a slipstream?
In theory,
but I don't think the ship
would hold up very long
under the quantum stresses.
Try to make
the modifications.
If there's a way we can bring
Voyager along for the ride,
I'm all for it.
Harry, B'Elanna, I want you
to take an engineering team
down to the
Dauntless.
Start working
on a way
to shut down
the slipstream drive
at a moment's notice.
Aye, Captain.
Once we have that safeguard
in place,
we can start making
the test flights.
I want this entire crew
to familiarize themselves
with that ship.
See to it.
Dismissed.
( door opens )
Tuvok...
Big day.
( door closes )
Indeed.
A way home.
We've been waiting for
this moment for years.
Why don't I feel
more enthusiastic?
Perhaps my
mental discipline
is rubbing off
on you.
Perhaps.
What do you think about
this little miracle of ours?
I share your concern
about the crew's safety.
We must take
every precaution.
Somehow, I don't think
standard diagnostics
and security
protocols
are gonna make me
feel any better.
Captain?
All of this is just
a little too perfect.
The alien genius
with the answers
to all of our problems.
The message
from Starfleet
telling us everything
we wanna hear...
A starship delivered
to our doorstep.
What more could
we ask for?
They even turned down
the beds.
The only thing missing was
chocolates on the pillows.
It does
seem convenient.
( sighing )
I can't put
my finger on it,
but from the moment
this all started,
I sensed something
was wrong.
It started when Arturis
boarded Voyager.
Exactly.
We'll proceed as planned,
but I want you to investigate
that ship from stem to stern,
and keep an eye on our guest.
See if you can find out
more about him.
Understood.
Let's hope we're
just suffering
from some good
old-fashioned paranoia.
Keep me posted.
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
So far, the crew
hasn't found any evidence
to support my doubts
about Arturis.
Nevertheless,
I've told them to keep looking
and to keep their optimism
in check.
But that's one order
I don't expect them
to follow to the letter...
SEVEN:
Daily log, Seven of Nine,
stardate 51981.6.
I've analyzed the quantum
slipstream technology
of the Dauntless.
It is similar to the transwarp
drive used by the Borg.
As a result, my expertise
will be crucial
to the mission's success.
Voyager's crew is counting
on that success,
but I find myself ambivalent,
so I am carrying out my...
JANEWAY:
Despite my apprehension,
I can't help but wonder
what I'll be doing
in three months' time.
Still guiding Voyager
through the Delta Quadrant,
searching for
a way home,
or looking up old friends
in Indiana?
SEVEN:
If we do return to Sector 001,
will I adapt
to human civilization?
A single Borg among billions
of individuals?
( beeping )
Initiate emergency shutdown
on my mark.
( beeping )
Now.
Quantum field strength
down to 90 percent.
80 percent.
It's leveling
off at 75.
We need to dampen the field
by at least 50 percent.
Try reversing the quantum field
polarities.
( beeping )
70 percent.
( dramatic theme playing )
55...
49 percent.
We did it.
We've got
our safety net.
One step closer
to home.
Tuvok wants us to run
a metallurgical analysis
of the bulkheads to look
for anything unusual.
Thank you.
You two run
the analysis.
I'll be on the Bridge
with Arturis.
Our resident genius said
he'd help me figure out
how to use the control
sequencers.
Lieutenant, you seem eager
to return to Earth.
Eager?
I wouldn't go
that far.
( beeping )
You were a member
of the Maquis.
Starfleet Command
will no doubt
hold you responsible
for a multitude of crimes.
You will find nothing on Earth
but adversity.
Well, that's looking
on the bright side.
Let's put it this way,
I'd rather face
the music at home
than spend the rest of my life
in the Delta Quadrant.
What about you?
Looking forward
to seeing Earth?
No.
I'm not surprised.
You think people are gonna
resent an ex-Maquis?
What about
an ex-drone?
We'll be
outcasts together.
I'm kidding,
Seven.
It's a joke.
Work on that
sense of humor.
It'll help you
make friends on Earth.
( door opens, closes )
KIM:
Seven, can you give me
a hand down here?
( beeping )
I'm picking up
an anomalous energy surge.
( beeping )
There are no
power conduits
running through
this section.
Believe me,
Seven,
one look at that big,
blue marble,
and you'll
fall in love.
It's got just about every
ecosystem you can think of,
and hundreds of different
humanoid species live there.
Vulcans, Bolians,
Ktarians...
If you like
Ktarians.
And there are several other
planets to choose from.
If you will
excuse me, Ensign,
I must speak
to the Captain.
Seven.
For what it's worth,
it won't be the same
without you.
( sighs )
( door opens, closes )
( beeping )
( beeping continues )
( tricorder beeping rapidly )
( crackling )
Kim to Tuvok.
TUVOK:
Tuvok here.
I'm on the Dauntless
in the Engine Room,
and I found something
that qualifies
as unusual.
I'll be
right there.
( dramatic theme playing )
( sighs )
Computer, display data block
14-beta, auxiliary display.
Seven,
I could use your help.
I'm trying to reconstruct
the last fragment
of the
Starfleet message.
Arturis said it was
irreparably damaged.
I know, but I think
he gave up too easily.
Intuition.
It's intuition
if I'm right.
I've designed a new
decryption algorithm.
Let's give it
a try.
Captain...
I will not be going with you
to the Alpha Quadrant.
I can understand
your reluctance.
It's been
hard enough
dealing with a crew
of 150 individual humans.
The prospect of
an entire planet
must be
overwhelming.
I am not
overwhelmed.
I simply do not wish
to live among humans.
Well, whether you like it
or not, you're one of us.
You've come a long way
from that drone
who stepped out of a Borg
alcove nine months ago.
Don't turn your back
on humanity now,
not when you're about to
take your biggest step...
Earth.
Your home.
I may have come
a long way,
but not in the
direction you think.
You've attempted to
influence my development.
You exposed me to your culture,
your ideals.
You hoped to shape me
in your own image,
but you have failed.
You may have noticed
our tendency to disagree.
Oh, I've noticed.
Then you must also recognize
that I do not share your values.
Your desire to explore space
is inefficient.
Your need for familial
connections is a weakness.
Your infatuation with this
planet is irrational.
I won't argue
that you've turned out
differently
than I expected,
and that we often have
conflicting points of view.
But right now,
the stakes are higher.
This crew needs
your expertise.
Abandon them,
and you diminish their chances
of getting home.
Irrelevant.
No, it's not.
We've given you a lot,
Seven.
It's time you gave
something in return.
I have...
on many occasions.
Now I refuse.
What would you do,
go back to the Collective?
I don't know.
Then what exactly
do you have in mind?
I don't know.
That's my point. You're asking
me to cast you adrift
in the Delta Quadrant,
alone and without support.
I wouldn't grant that request
to any member of this crew,
because
it's too dangerous.
I will survive.
On what,
Borg perfection?
Precisely.
I don't buy it.
This isn't about
your independence,
your superiority.
This is about your fear.
You're not making
this choice
because you've
outgrown humanity.
( whispering ):
I think you're afraid
to go back to Earth.
( console beeping )
( dramatic theme playing )
( in normal voice ):
The algorithm's working.
It's reconstructing
the data block.
( distorted speech )
That's strange.
I thought we already recovered
this part of the message.
Perhaps it is an addendum
from the Admiral.
You did designate him
a windbag.
Oh, I don't think so.
The data index doesn't match.
This is a completely
different message.
Apologies from everyone
at Starfleet Command.
We've had our best people
working around the clock
trying to find
a wormhole,
a new means of propulsion,
anything to get you back home.
But despite
our best efforts...
I know it's not
what you were hoping.
But we have sent you
all the data
we've collected
on the Delta Quadrant.
With any luck, you'll find at
least some part of it useful,
maybe enough to shave
a few years off your trip.
Safe journey.
We hope to see you soon.
Your intuition
was correct.
Unfortunately.
Arturis must have created
a false message.
It sure as hell
looks that way.
( comlink beeps )
Janeway to Tuvok.
TUVOK:
Yes, Captain.
My suspicions
have been confirmed.
Arturis tampered with
Starfleet's message.
JANEWAY:
The Dauntless isn't
what it appears to be.
I agree.
We've discovered
alien technology
behind a bulkhead
in Engineering.
I can't identify it.
Where's Arturis now?
On the Dauntless Bridge,
working with Lieutenant Torres.
JANEWAY:
Go to the Bridge,
but don't tip our hand.
I'll be there with a full
security team within minutes.
Understood.
Let's get weapons.
Don't touch that!
You almost kicked us
into slipstream drive.
Oh.
I wouldn't want to do that.
( speaks in Klingon )
No problem.
You speak Klingon.
I do now.
Your Captain was kind enough
to let me review
your linguistic database.
I only speak
a few phrases myself.
Oh, a shame.
It's a robust language.
A little too robust
for me.
( whooshing )
Evacuate
the repair teams.
Captain?
JANEWAY: Do it.
Explain yourself.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You fabricated the message
from Starfleet.
I recovered
the real transmission,
the one you said
was irreparably damaged.
That's absurd.
Starfleet didn't send us
this vessel.
And you're not here to help.
Is this your ship?
Please, I--
Stay calm.
There must be
an explanation.
I tried to ignore
my gut feelings,
because I got carried away
with the excitement
of getting home.
But you preyed on that,
didn't you?
You took advantage of our hopes,
and now I want to know why.
I...
believe that there is
a threat here, Captain.
But not from me.
I didn't feel it was my place
to make accusations,
but I saw her
reconfigure several
key algorithms
two days ago
in the
Astrometrics Lab.
And it seemed obvious.
She must have been tampering
with the Starfleet message.
You are lying.
She's been sabotaging
your every effort
to reach Earth.
You don't have to believe me,
Captain.
You can find the evidence you
need in her personal database.
Evidence you undoubtedly
put there yourself,
just in case you got caught.
Take him to Voyager.
Throw him
in the brig.
( grunts )
( grunting )
( all grunting )
( ominous theme playing )
Janeway to Voyager.
Beam us out of here.
He's trying to deflect
our transporters.
Stand by.
I've got everyone
but Seven and the Captain.
He's found a way to block
their transport.
The ship's going
into slipstream mode.
Pursuit course.
( rumbling )
( dramatic theme playing )
We lost them,
Commander.
Tom, bring the warp core
modifications online.
We're going
after them.
Sir, we haven't even had
a trial run yet.
There's no time
like the present.
( sighs )
Where are you
taking us?
Home.
How'd you create
the Starfleet Bridge?
Holograms?
Particle synthesis.
Beyond your
understanding.
Is this what
your people do?
Prey on
innocent ships?
Innocent.
Typical of
Captain Janeway.
Self-righteous.
If I've offended you
or your people in some way,
please tell me.
Diplomacy, Captain?
Your diplomacy
destroyed my world!
JANEWAY:
What? What are you saying?
You negotiated
an agreement
with the
Borg Collective.
Safe passage
through their space,
and in return,
you helped them defeat
one of their enemies.
Species 8472.
In your colorful
language, yes,
Species 8472.
Did it ever occur to you
that there were those of us
in the Delta Quadrant with
a vested interest in that war?
Victory would have meant
annihilation of the Borg,
but you couldn't see beyond
the bow of your own ship!
In my estimation,
Species 8472 posed
a greater threat than the Borg.
Who were you
to make that decision?
A stranger
to this Quadrant?
There wasn't exactly time
to take a poll.
I had to act quickly.
My people managed to elude
the Borg for centuries...
Outwitting them,
always one step ahead.
But in recent years, the Borg
began to weaken our defenses.
They were closing in,
and Species 8472
was our last hope
to defeat them.
You took that
away from us!
The outer colonies
were the first to fall.
Twenty-three
in a matter of hours.
Our sentry vessels
tossed aside.
No defense
against the storm.
And by the time they had
surrounded our star system,
hundreds of cubes...
We had already surrendered
to our own terror.
A few of us managed
to survive...ten, 20,000.
I was fortunate.
I escaped
with a vessel,
alone...
but alive.
I don't
blame them.
They were just drones,
acting with
their collective instinct.
You!
You had a choice!
I am sorry for what happened
to your people,
but try to understand.
I couldn't have known.
It took me months
to find you.
I watched and waited
for my opportunity
to make you pay
for what you'd done.
Then,
the Starfleet message.
And I knew that your
selfish desire to get home
would surface again,
that I could lure you
to this vessel.
That I could see to it that
you'd all be assimilated
and spend the rest
of eternity as Borg!
I was hoping...
to get your entire crew,
but I'll settle for
the two of you.
( ominous theme playing )
( console beeping )
In a matter of hours,
this ship
will return
to my homeworld...
...inside Borg space.
When that happens, you will
be assimilated as well.
That's irrelevant.
This is what you wanted
all along, isn't it?
To go back
to your Collective?
You should thank me.
( ominous theme swells )
( dramatic theme playing )
Report.
( sighs ):
We're at full impulse,
but we're not breaking through
the quantum barrier.
I'm having trouble controlling
the field parameters.
I need more power to
the deflector.
Bridge to Torres.
B'ELANNA: I'm already on it,
Commander.
Stand by.
Reroute auxiliary power
to deflector control.
Make sure that quantum
warp field is stable.
MAN:
Aye, Lieutenant.
( rumbling )
Deflector at maximum.
I'm focusing
the quantum field.
Make it quick.
Hull temperature's
at critical.
We're at
slipstream velocity.
KIM:
Structural integrity
is down by 9 percent.
We've got less
than an hour
before the hull
starts to buckle.
I've located
their slipstream.
I'm aligning ours
to match.
We're right
behind them.
How far behind?
Just a few minutes.
TUVOK:
Is there any way
to increase our speed?
None.
We're at maximum.
Maintain course.
If I know
the Captain,
she's already
got a plan.
Any ideas?
Not presently.
We better
think of something.
We come face-to-face
with your former family
in less than an hour,
and that's one reunion
I'd like to miss.
Unless, of course,
you're looking forward
to rejoining
the Collective.
I do not
believe I am.
Not the
ringing opposition
I was hoping for,
but I'll take it.
A drone could walk
through this force field
like it was thin air.
Is there enough
Borg technology
left in your body
to let it adapt?
If I activate the
appropriate nanoprobes,
I could alter
my bioelectric field.
However, I would need to
adjust my cranial implant.
Would a microfilament
do the trick?
It might.
Then let's
get you one.
Once you get outside,
access that control panel
and disable
the force field.
Then we'll try to
reach the engine room.
And employ the emergency
shutdown procedure.
Sufficient.
You will need
to cross-link the third
and sixth nodules.
Dj vu.
Captain?
If I recall,
this is where
our relationship began,
in a brig
nine months ago.
I severed you
from the Collective,
and you weren't exactly
happy about it.
No, I was not.
In case I never get
a chance to say this...
I realize that I've been
hard on you at times,
but it was never
out of anger
or regret that
I brought you on board.
I'm your Captain.
That means I can't
always be a friend.
Understand?
No.
However,
if we are assimilated,
our thoughts
will become one,
and I'm sure I will
understand perfectly.
A joke, Captain.
You yourself have encouraged me
to use my sense of humor.
Well,
it's nice to know
you've taken some
of my advice to heart.
You were correct,
Captain.
Hm?
My desire to remain
in the Delta Quadrant
was based on fear.
I am no longer
Borg,
but the prospect of
becoming human is...
unsettling.
I don't know
where I belong.
You belong with us.
( electronic crackling )
The adaptations
are complete.
( console beeping )
( force field whooshing )
We're in business.
( dramatic theme playing )
I can't initiate
the emergency shutdown.
Our commands are being
blocked from the Bridge.
He's detected us.
( rumbling )
The ship's velocity
has just increased.
At our
present speed,
we will enter Borg space
in less than 12 minutes.
Do we still have access
to the power distribution grid?
Yes.
If we can't throw on the brakes,
let's swerve the wheel.
Send a power surge
into the starboard thrusters.
The torsional stress
at these speeds
could tear the ship apart.
It's either that
or join the hive. Do it.
If we're still
in one piece,
try to gain control
of navigation.
I'll be on
the Bridge.
We have a game
of Velocity
scheduled for tomorrow,
Holodeck One.
I expect you
to keep the appointment.
Aye, Captain.
( grunting )
( panting )
( dramatic theme swells )
( sighing )
Sorry about
the bumpy ride.
You can slow this ship down,
but you can't stop it.
In four minutes,
Captain Janeway will be gone,
and a new drone
will be born.
Don't count on it.
( rumbling )
Seven of Nine has accessed
your navigational systems.
You taught us how
to use this ship
a little too well.
I can't begin to
imagine your loss,
but try to see beyond
your desire for revenge.
Revenge is all
I have left.
No, no. As long as you're alive,
there's hope.
Your people's
accomplishments
their knowledge, their dignity
can survive in you.
End this.
( loud beeping )
( booming )
I've just destroyed
the navigational controls.
No one can stop
this ship now,
not even me.
Two minutes
to Borg space.
( rumble )
( both groaning )
( dramatic theme continues )
Direct hit.
The vessel's
shields are down.
Transporter
standing by.
Get a lock
on our people.
( grunts )
( panting )
( beeping )
Voyager.
Come with me.
It's not too late.
It is for you.
I've got them, Commander.
Transporter Room Two.
Alter our slipstream,
hard starboard.
Take us back
the way we came.
( dramatic theme playing )
COLLECTIVE:
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
( tranquil theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's log, supplemental.
We remained in the quantum
slipstream for an hour
before it finally
collapsed.
Our diagnostics
have concluded
that we can't risk
using this technology again,
but we did manage to get
300 light years closer
to home.
COMPUTER:
Full impact.
Final round to Janeway.
Winner, Janeway.
Nice play.
You almost had me.
Almost.
Go again?
I must report
to the Astrometrics Lab.
There is work to be done.
Work?
I gave the crew strict orders
to take some R&amp;R
over the next few days,
and that includes you.
There are
more pressing needs.
I am attempting to design
another method of traveling
at slipstream velocities
without damaging Voyager.
I thought
that was impossible.
Impossible is a word
that humans use far too often.
I wish to continue
my efforts.
A few days ago,
you were ready to abandon ship,
and here you are, practically
laying in a course to Earth.
As we approached Borg space,
I began to reevaluate my future.
The prospect of
becoming a drone...
was unappealing.
Sometimes you've got
to look back
in order to move forward.
Sounds to me like
you're starting
to embrace
your humanity.
No.
But as I said,
nothing is impossible.
( tranquil theme playing )
Computer...
( computer beeping )
...one more game.
( beeping continues )
( triumphant theme playing )