MALE:
Citizens of Earth,
your destiny is in my hands.
Those of you who acquiesce
to my demands
will be treated fairly.
Oppose me,
and you face a dire fate indeed
as my slaves in the mines
of Mercury.
You have one hour.
You'll never get away
with this.
Oh, but I shall.
Your once-proud country
will fall to its knees.
How ironic that I am
using your rocket ship
to lead my space force
into battle.
You're wrong, Chaotica.
Before you came on board,
someone pushed
the self-destruct button.
In three minutes,
we'll all be dead.
No!
( door opens )
The jig is up, Your Majesty.
Captain Proton.
Spaceman First Class,
Protector of Earth
Scourge of Intergalactic Evil...
at your service.
But I saw you fall
into the fiery mouth
of that volcano.
It takes more than
a little lava
to stop Captain Proton.
Now, I want you to call off
your invasion
and give me back
my rocket ship.
There is one force
in this universe
that even you cannot defeat.
( screaming )
The same to you.
Doc.
Mr. Paris.
I should have known
it was you
monopolizing the holodeck.
Who is this
insolent fool?
Uh, he's one
of our men.
Computer, adjust the Doctor's
spectral frequency.
I have no interest
in your frivolous fantasy.
I'm here to rehearse a duet
from Don Carlo,
and you've already gone
three minutes into my sched--
Enough!
Robot, attack.
( screams )
CHAOTICA:
Destroy them.
Start with him.
Computer, freeze program.
( computer beeps )
Doc, this is
the final chapter--
"Satan's Robot
Conquers the World."
We can't stop now.
Does the phrase
"to be continued"
mean anything
to you?
Your opera can wait.
This program is a waste
of photonic energy.
Oh, really?
Take a look around you.
This is how the 20th century
saw the future.
We are studying sociology.
Perhaps you can teach a course
at Starfleet Academy.
"Satan's Robot:
An Historical Overview."
( scoffs )
( alarm blaring )
Bridge to Holodeck 1.
What's going on down there?
KIM:
Oh, nothing, Commander.
Just a little power surge.
Says here the hologrid
just blew out.
PARIS:
We're fixing it now, sir.
Well, make it quick.
The last thing we need
is a broken holodeck.
Seven, I want good news.
That's an order.
Then I must disobey.
I have no good news
to report.
I've completed an astrometric
scan of the entire region.
There are no star systems
within 2,500 light-years.
Nothing?
Nothing.
Why can't we see any
stars beyond that?
There are heavy concentrations
of theta radiation.
It has occluded our sensors.
Any other ships
out there?
None. We are alone.
( sighs )
Every sailor's nightmare.
SEVEN:
Commander?
CHAKOTAY:
It's like being becalmed
in the middle of the ocean.
If it weren't for sensors,
we wouldn't even
know we were at warp.
We've only been crossing
this expanse for two months
and we're already feeling
the strain.
How do we last
another two years?
We will adapt.
Easier said than done.
Shall I inform
the Captain of my findings?
No.
I'll tell her.
( door opens, closes )
( dramatic theme playing )
CHAKOTAY:
First Officer's Log,
Stardate 52081.2.
It's been 53 days since we
entered this desolate region.
If we want to continue
our course toward home,
we have no choice
but to cross it.
We won't have an opportunity to
take on fresh supplies or fuel,
so I've ordered all departments
to create an energy reserve.
We're using power cells
to stockpile deuterium.
TORRES:
This won't be much
of a briefing.
There's nothing new
to report.
Humor me.
All right. Let's see.
Warp core's at
peak efficiency,
just like last week
and the week before that.
And my Engineering staff
is going stir-crazy.
Thanks.
Ensign?
Nada.
Can you be more specific?
All systems
are operating
within normal
parameters.
Anything new on sensors?
I detected a sudden increase
of theta radiation
in the vicinity.
Source?
Unknown.
Could be worth a look.
Finally, some excitement.
Radiation.
( chuckling )
Next piece of business.
Crew morale.
Deteriorating...
obviously.
I have a few suggestions
that might boost
people's spirits.
Please.
Rotate crew assignments.
Add variety
to the daily routine.
I myself wouldn't mind
squeezing in
a little tactical training.
Noted.
NEELIX:
And the holodecks
have been in high demand.
I was thinking...
we could install a few emitters
in Cargo Bay 2...
turn it into a third holodeck.
Hear, hear.
CHAKOTAY:
See to it, Harry.
One other item, sir.
Point of, uh, concern
among some of the crew.
It's--
Well, it's the Captain.
She's been a bit
elusive lately.
What's your point?
People take comfort
in talking to her.
When they see that the Captain's
happy, they're happy.
Rumor has it she never
leaves her quarters.
Captain's privilege.
She'll come to the Bridge
if and when she's needed.
Spare us the protocol,
Chakotay.
It's pretty odd,
you've got to admit it.
It's her choice.
She can run this ship
from wherever the hell
she wants to. Understood?
Yeah.
Sure.
( sighs )
We're all feeling the pressure,
including me.
Listen, maybe we've got
the wrong attitude.
Let's think of this
as a two-year vacation.
Dismissed.
That's a great idea, Harry.
Wow, Harry.
You're a real genius.
How do you come up with
these brilliant ideas?
You're such an optimistic guy.
( doors opening, closing )
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeps )
( gasping )
( panting )
Computer, lights, maximum level.
( beeping )
Bergamot tea, hot.
First thing in the morning,
I replicate some curtains.
Predictable.
Hmm?
The Novokovich gambit. You
always use that opening move.
That's because you
always fall for it.
( sighing ):
I feel like we've played
this match a hundred times.
Derada is a game of subtlety.
Too subtle for me.
Hmm. I'll bet.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, if it doesn't involve
Klingon painsticks...
Good night.
There you go.
Just when I'm winning.
Who's predictable?
You don't want to start a fight
with me now.
Not at 3 a.m.
Three in the morning,
4 in the afternoon...
what's the difference?
You're angry 24 hours a day.
Everything is
a joke to you.
Good evening...
Or should I say good morning?
I guess you couldn't
sleep, either.
Oh, why sleep when we're
having so much fun?
He's joking, Neelix.
We're all supposed to laugh.
NEELIX:
I certainly am
laughing
on the inside...
Smiling, anyway.
Let's start a new game.
Cards?
A little snack?
No. I have a better idea.
Why don't we make a schedule,
a fight rotation?
We can optimize
our resources.
I can start one,
then you can start one...
Please...
I am really tired
of these games.
Well, then don't play them.
( shouts ): Stop!
You are senior officers!
You are supposed to be setting
an example for the rest--
( gasping ):
The rest of the crew.
( hyperventilating )
Neelix?
I can't breathe.
Paris to Sick Bay.
Some morale officer
I turned out to be.
I've given you
a mild sedative.
It should control
the urge to hyperventilate
and alleviate
some of your anxiety.
Anxiety?
Anxiety's what I feel
when I burn a pot roast.
This... This is more like...
Dizziness? Nausea?
Unspeakable dread?
Yes.
Nihiliphobia,
the fear of nothingness,
or in layman's terms,
the fear of...
nothingness.
If it's any consolation,
I can relate to it.
I go into a void every time
I'm deactivated...
emptiness, complete
and utter oblivion.
I'll admit, it was
unsettling at first...
The existential horror
of it all...
You're not helping,
Doctor.
Sorry.
My point is,
you'll get used to it.
I hope so.
( door opens )
( dramatic theme playing )
SEVEN:
Commander...
am I disturbing you?
No.
Is the Astrometrics Lab
designated for recreational use?
I come here to meditate.
Needless to say,
the view from my quarters
has been less
than stellar lately.
Astronomical phenomena
help you to focus your mind.
Yes. I imagine that each star
represents a single thought.
Meditation...
it rejuvenates you?
Indeed it does.
I suggest you try
Borg regeneration.
It's much more efficient.
A simple cortical implant
would be required.
Another time, perhaps.
( beeping )
What is it?
Long-range sensors are detecting
more theta radiation.
Dangerously high levels.
Source?
Unknown.
It's probably nothing, just...
background theta radiation.
But it could mean
there's someone nearby.
JANEWAY:
Distance?
Approximately
25 light-years.
It's a long shot,
but alter course.
Yes, ma'am.
If that's all,
Commander...
Actually, I'd like
to make a request.
I've been saving up
my holodeck rations,
and I've got
three full hours coming.
Any chance
I might persuade you to join me
for a few rounds of Velocity?
It'll help clear
your mind.
My mind is perfectly clear.
Then what if I told you I'm
not leaving until you join me?
I'd say, "Have a seat.
It'll be a while."
Then I'll be blunt.
You've picked a bad time
to isolate yourself
from the crew.
This ship needs a Captain,
especially now.
Would you be satisfied with
"I'm just catching up
on some reading?"
I'm not sure
I understand it myself.
It started when we
entered this--
What does the crew call it?
The Void.
Charming.
Oh, what I wouldn't give
for a few Borg cubes about now,
anything for
a little distraction.
Strange as it sounds...
I almost long for the days
when we were under
constant attack.
No time to stop and think
about how we got stranded
in the Delta Quadrant.
How did we end up here,
Chakotay?
Answer me.
We were faced
with a difficult choice.
We had the means to get home,
but using it would have put
an innocent people at risk
so we decided to stay.
No... No, no.
I decided to stay.
I made that choice
for everyone.
We're alive and well,
and we've gathered enough
data about this Quadrant
to keep Starfleet scientists
busy for decades.
Our mission's been a success.
Very same words
I've been telling myself
for the past four years.
But then we hit this Void,
and I started to realize
how empty those words sound.
Kathryn...
I made an error in judgment,
Chakotay.
It was shortsighted
and it was selfish,
and now all of us
are paying for my mistake.
So if you don't mind, Commander,
I'll pass on that little game.
And I'll leave shipboard morale
in your capable hands.
If the crew asks for me,
tell them the Captain
sends her regards.
( dramatic theme playing )
( clarinet plays melody
in minor key )
( door opens )
Sir.
Relax, Ensign.
Anything to report?
Not even a stray electron,
but I did finish
writing my concerto.
I call it
Echoes of the Void.
Got a minute?
Too many, in fact.
Tell me what you think.
( continues playing
in minor key )
Now, when we last saw
our heroes,
they had just retaken
their rocket ship.
Dr. Chaotica had escaped,
but he left behind
his trusty robot
to foil Captain Proton.
My designation?
Ah, right.
You're Constance Goodheart.
You're...my secretary.
Secretary?
Yeah. You tag along
on all the missions.
Now, I want you to keep
the robot occupied
while I save Earth.
Computer, run program.
Citizen of Earth,
surrender.
Do not resist.
I am Borg.
( voice slows down):
Surrender...
The robot has been
neutralized.
May I leave now?
Come on, Seven.
Give it a chance.
The galaxy's at stake.
( continues playing concerto)
( alarm beeping )
We've dropped out of warp.
We're losing power.
Switch to auxiliary.
No effect.
( dramatic theme playing )
( indistinct chatter )
KIM:
I was hoping for
a change of pace,
but a blackout isn't
exactly what I had in mind.
I'll try tapping into
the energy reserves.
( panicky breathing )
MAN 1:
Double-check the radio relay.
MAN 2:
Man the lock plate.
MAN 3:
Yeah, I'll get on
that right away.
( people continue shouting
indistinctly )
Get inside
those plasma injectors!
Infuse them manually
if you have to.
SEVEN:
Lieutenant...
PARIS:
Just a second.
I'm not sure
how to work this thing.
Captain Proton
to the rescue.
It's not exactly
Starfleet issue.
( beeping )
Shipwide power loss?
Everything's off-line--
Main power, auxiliary...
Independent subsystems
are operational.
Environmental controls,
holodecks...
Reroute power
from this holodeck
to the emergency relays.
Yes, ma'am.
No luck.
The hologrid is frozen.
( panicky breathing )
Neelix.
Don't mind me.
There's been
a power loss.
Nothing to worry about.
Who's worried?
Come on.
Take deep breaths,
nice and slow.
That's it.
( beeping )
Bingo.
We've got
partial sensors.
I found the cause
of our power drain.
It's some kind
of dampening field.
The source is
off the port bow.
That's about
all I can tell you.
On screen.
Do we have the power
to launch
a photon torpedo?
Maybe one. Why?
Perhaps we could shed some light
on our predicament.
I'm reconfiguring the torpedo
to emit a sustained
polyluminous burst.
A "warp flare."
Precisely.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I need something
to pry open this hatch.
( growling )
( yells )
Computer,
disengage safety protocols!
I saw something!
Over there.
I'm telling you,
I saw something.
I may be
nihiliphobic,
but my eyes
work just fine.
( suspenseful theme continues )
( breathing nearby )
I can hear breathing.
( growls )
Follow me.
Yes, ma'am.
Torpedo reconfigured.
Away.
I can barely see
the injector ports.
How about a little light
over here?
We can do better than that.
This power cell should be enough
to get emergency power
back on line.
TORRES:
Up here!
We'll hook it up directly
to the EPS manifold.
Emergency power
just came back.
We've got tactical.
Raising shields.
TORRES:
The warp core's
on line.
Janeway to Bridge.
Report.
TUVOK:
The dampening field
has been blocked, Captain.
We are surrounded
by three alien vessels.
Seventeen intruders
are on board.
The ships aren't
responding to hails.
We do have
weapons on line.
Tuvok, target the ship
off our port bow.
Fire a few warning shots.
TUVOK:
Shields down to 64 percent.
Do we have
propulsion?
Not yet.
( groaning )
He was attacked
by an intruder.
These burns
are severe.
( weapon firing in distance )
( grunts )
I disabled the alien.
It may still be alive.
Bring it to Sick Bay.
Shields are down.
They're reinitializing
the dampening field.
We're losing power.
Not again.
They've stopped
their attack.
They're beaming
off the ship.
There's another vessel
approaching.
( dramatic theme playing )
We're
being hailed.
On screen.
I'm Lieutenant Commander Tuvok
of the Federation--
I had to fire
13 spatial charges
to drive those ships off.
I expect to be compensated.
Of course.
Now...
tell me...
what are you doing
in the middle of nowhere?
( transporter beeping )
The bio-filters
are detecting
high levels of
theta radiation.
Compensate.
Welcome aboard.
I'm afraid we'll have
to talk here.
You appear to be leaking.
Yes, yes. My...
isolation suit.
Don't be alarmed.
We'd prefer to be
on the safe side, Mister...?
Emck. Controller Emck,
Malon export vessel,
eleventh gradient.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
and a relief--
EMCK:
I'd advise you
to turn around immediately.
There are more
of those creatures ahead,
thousands of vessels.
They are almost impossible
to detect.
You won't survive
another attack.
We can't go back.
We're crossing this
expanse to reach our home.
Mmm.
Then, uh...
it appears you'll
be coming with me.
What do you
mean?
There's a spatial vortex
a few light-years from here.
It leads directly to
the other side
of the expanse.
We've been using it
for years.
That would get us
out of the Void
and cut two years
off our journey home.
Well, thank you again.
I'm curious, Mr. Emck.
What are you doing here,
besides rescuing
starships in distress?
Ah. I'm on a...
transport mission.
My sensors tell me
that one of the creatures
is still aboard your ship.
It was injured
during the attack.
Our Doctor's treating it.
Why?
Enough questions.
Give me the creature
and I'll take you to the vortex.
Well, my apologies, Mr. Emck,
but I'd like to know
what's going on here.
Are you at war
with these beings?
None of your concern.
Your vessel seems
to be leaking
large amounts
of theta radiation.
What kind of transport mission
are you on, exactly?
My ship will depart
in two hours.
Cooperate or stay behind.
I won't be coming
to your rescue
when the creatures return.
I'm finished here.
( dramatic theme playing )
( console beeps )
I think it's time we heard
the other side of the story.
Watch your step.
I've had
to lower the lights.
My patient is extremely
photosensitive.
That could explain
why they dampened our power.
My feelings exactly.
From what I can tell,
this life-form may be
indigenous to the Void.
His physiology has evolved to
survive in complete darkness.
His condition?
Minor injuries,
phaser wounds
to the chest and neck.
But that's the least
of his problems.
He's dying, Captain.
Every organ is degrading
at the cellular level.
JANEWAY:
Theta radiation poisoning.
DOCTOR:
The final stages.
My guess is he's been exposed
to it over a long period.
There's nothing
I can do.
I'd like a word with him.
I'm Kathryn Janeway,
Captain of this vessel.
You are allies
with the Malon.
No.
We're simply trying
to cross this region.
We never met the
Malon before today.
They will want me.
Well, I have no intention
of giving you to them.
You're not
a captive here.
( shivering grunt )
Doctor.
Are you at war
with the Malon?
Their ships are poison.
The theta radiation.
They're killing us.
Why? What do they want from you?
Nothing.
This will help
alleviate the pain.
I don't understand.
We were ignorant.
We attacked you.
Forgive us.
Of course,
but I need to understand.
You say the Malon
are killing your people,
but there must
be a reason.
They're poisoning our space.
We don't know why.
( gasping )
( medical instrument beeps )
He's in respiratory distress.
We need to get him
back to his people.
They might know
how to treat him.
I will show you how.
I need a workstation.
Route it to the helm.
If you enter
the coordinates,
my pilot will set a course.
I am grateful.
Take the Bridge.
I'll stay here.
We still don't have a defense
against their dampening field.
If they decide
to attack again--
I'm confident
they won't.
Finally something
to put in my logbook.
Tuvok.
I need your advice.
A first.
Look, I realize
we're not exactly best friends.
From day one, we've kept
each other at arm's length,
but I've always respected
your judgment,
and right now, I could use
a little Vulcan clarity.
Proceed.
It's the Captain.
As you may have noticed, she's
isolated herself from the crew.
She believes that she made
an error in judgment
four years ago,
that she's responsible
for stranding Voyager
in the Delta Quadrant.
She told you?
No.
I've been observing her behavior
for the past four years.
Guilt has been
her constant companion.
You've known her
longer than anyone.
Have you ever
seen her like this?
Only once.
It was during
her first year
as a Commander
on the USS Billings.
She sent an away team
to survey a volcanic moon.
Their shuttle was damaged
by a magma eruption,
and three crew members
were severely injured.
The next day, she returned
to the moon, alone,
to complete the survey.
She wanted the crew to know
that their suffering
had not been in vain.
She could have been killed.
Seeking redemption.
Precisely.
Captain Janeway's methods
are...unorthodox.
It is her strength
as a leader,
but, unfortunately, it is also
her greatest weakness.
Stubborn as a Klingon.
To put it mildly.
If she tries something
like that again,
I want to be ready,
and I'm going
to need your support.
( dramatic theme playing )
( computer beeping )
We're at the coordinates.
All stop. Shields up.
Tuvok.
Nothing on sensors.
Bridge to Captain.
We've arrived.
Stand by.
They're here...
but I must tell them
you are a friend.
Your communications system?
( console beeping )
I'm picking up photonic surges.
They're all around us.
Captain, we've got
company. Eight ships.
Twelve more approaching.
Let's run
a full bio-scan.
We have lived here
for millions of years
undisturbed,
until the Malon came.
Captain, every one of them
appears to be suffering
from theta radiation
exposure.
ALIEN:
We tell them
they are killing us.
They won't listen.
We try to stop them.
They're too strong.
What about the vortex, can you
close it? Keep them out?
We don't know how.
Your ship is powerful.
Your people resourceful.
We need your help.
( comm beeps )
Bridge to Captain.
They're locking
onto the alien in Sick Bay.
Lower the shields.
Will you help us?
Poison.
The vessel is ejecting
massive quantities
of contaminated
antimatter.
Their cargo holds
are loaded with it,
over 90 million
isotons.
Hail them.
EMCK:
Captain.
You've decided to join us.
Send the creature to...
JANEWAY:
That won't be possible. We've
returned him to his people.
You wanted the life-form
because you were afraid
we'd uncover your...
transport mission.
I said this was
none of your concern.
Well, it is now.
You're using their space
as a dumping ground
for your
antimatter waste. Why?
My civilization produces
over 6 billion isotons
of industrial byproduct
every day.
This region is
a perfect disposal site.
How convenient...
for you.
A spacial vortex
to the middle of nowhere,
far away
from your own system.
Out of sight,
out of mind.
The problem is,
somebody lives here.
One species.
JANEWAY: One's enough.
We didn't come here
to debate the issue.
We came here to offer
a peaceful solution.
What kind of solution?
My people use
antimatter as well,
but we found ways to
purify the reactant
so there's no
toxic waste.
We'll show you.
Guide us through
the vortex.
We can meet with
your scientists
on the other side,
exchange information.
Show me now.
Stand by for transport.
Commander, take our
guest to Engineering
and give him
a demonstration.
Let's turn our sensors
on that vortex.
I want to know exactly
how it works...
just in case
diplomacy fails.
Do you intend
to destroy it?
TORRES:
The residual antimatter's
then processed
in a transkinetic chamber
where it's broken down
on a subatomic level.
What about
the theta radiation?
Oh, it's absorbed by a series
of radiometric converters.
We recycle the energy,
use it to power
everything
from life support
to replicators.
We don't have this kind
of conversion technology.
Our scans
of your freighter
show that you have
plasma manifolds.
The engineering principles
are the same.
We're not saying this
won't take some effort.
You're looking at several
months of retrofitting,
depending on the size
of your fleet.
All the schematics
are here
and we'd be willing
to work with you,
get you started.
We can even provide you
with some converters.
Ingenious design.
Our engineers
would be pleased.
This would solve a lot
of problems on my world.
Unfortunately,
it would also
put me out of business.
Sorry?
Your technology would throw
the waste-export
industry into chaos.
Before long, I'd be obsolete,
heh.
Oh, I came here
hoping your claims
were exaggerated,
but I can see they're not.
You can keep your solution.
You lying--
B'Elanna.
We went through
this whole song and dance,
and he never had any intention
of working with us.
That's not important.
What matters is
that we're talking now.
We're proposing changes,
some of them difficult,
but progress can also bring
new opportunities.
Given time, this could turn
to your advantage.
( wheezing laugh )
I already have
the advantage--
The vortex.
No one knows about it
except me and my crew.
By ejecting my cargo here,
I cut expenses in half.
I won't sacrifice that.
I guess mass murder doesn't
factor into your profit margin.
You care so much
about these creatures, stay.
I'm sorry you won't
listen to reason,
but don't expect us
to walk away from this.
You've scanned my vessel.
You've seen my firepower.
You wouldn't survive
10 seconds
in a conflict with me.
Get him out of here.
( dramatic theme playing )
Ah!
( sighs )
JANEWAY:
Options?
CHAKOTAY:
We fight our way past them,
navigate the vortex
on our own.
Once we're
on the other side,
we contact the
Malon authorities
and blow the
whistle on Emck.
We give them
the reclamation technology
and continue on our way home.
Exactly.
Even if we did
get through the vortex,
there's no guarantee the Malon
will do the right thing...
if Mr. Emck is
any indication.
As long as this vortex exists,
the inhabitants
of this region are at risk.
Any chance we could
destroy it?
I believe so,
but there's a catch.
We'll have to collapse it
from this end
where it's dimensional
radius is weakest.
We'd be closing
our shortcut out of here.
Two more years in the Void.
I can live with that.
But I'm not sure I can.
Four years ago,
I destroyed the Caretaker's
Array to protect the Ocampa.
That "act of compassion"
stranded this crew
in the Delta Quadrant.
I'm not about
to give that order again.
This situation is
a little different.
Oh, it's close enough.
I'm asking this crew
to make too big a sacrifice.
I won't make
that same mistake.
If you have another
option, I'm listening.
Chakotay,
there's no one I trust
more than you.
You're a fine First Officer.
Are you ready
to Captain this ship?
Yes.
Assemble the crew.
( dramatic theme playing )
Captain on the Bridge.
JANEWAY:
At ease.
Harry, how have you been?
Just fine, ma'am.
Good.
We've missed you,
Captain.
Likewise.
I'll make this brief.
Your orders are to proceed
to the vortex.
Use whatever means necessary
to fight your way
past the Malon freighter.
I'll stay behind
in a shuttlecraft
and destroy the vortex.
Tuvok, I'll need
a class-2 shuttle
armed with photon torpedoes.
Tom, set a course for...
TORRES:
Forget it.
We're not going to let you
die out here.
Have a little faith, B'Elanna.
I'll have a shuttle, plenty
of rations. I'll survive.
Alone in the Delta Quadrant?
No offense, but...
I've made my decision.
What about us?
Don't we have a say?
He's right,
Captain.
I'd be willing
to brave this Void
if it meant
keeping you with us.
Tom...set a course.
Lieutenant,
I gave you an order.
I can't follow
that order, ma'am.
Harry, take the helm.
I'm sorry, Captain.
( dramatic theme grows somber )
I will not comply.
What's a hologram to do?
As you can see,
you're not the only one
who's had time
to evaluate the past.
Yes, I can see that.
You realize
you could all be hanged
for mutiny.
Looks like we need
another option.
We fire torpedoes
the instant we cross
the threshold.
As the vortex begins
to collapse,
we jump into high warp.
There'll be a massive
shock wave on our tail.
I'll reinforce
the aft shielding.
There's still one obstacle,
the Malon.
Antimatter waste has
weakened the bulkhead
surrounding
their cargo hold.
A direct phaser strike
should disable them.
Poetic justice.
Indeed.
You realize it will reduce
our chance
of getting through.
Chance is irrelevant.
We will succeed.
A vote of Borg confidence.
Who could argue with that?
All right.
Back to your stations.
Let's do it.
CHAKOTAY:
Red Alert. Set a course
for the vortex.
All hands
to battle stations.
You told them.
They knew coming in.
Let's just say
I wouldn't be
a fine First Officer
if I hadn't.
( somber theme swells
dramatically )
( crashing )
Return fire.
Hit them with
everything we've got.
Their shields
are holding.
Open a channel.
This is Voyager.
Stand down your weapons
and fall back.
( crashing )
I'll take that as a "no."
The vortex?
Two million kilometers
dead ahead.
Bridge to Engineering.
We're approaching
the vortex.
Bring the aft shielding
on line.
Acknowledged.
See you on
the other side.
Status?
The port nacelle's
been ruptured.
We're venting
plasma.
Can you get us out of here
on one engine, Tom?
I think so.
Torpedoes
armed and ready.
On my order, Tuvok.
We'll only get
one shot at this.
They're firing
spatial charges.
Evade them.
( exhales )
Captain Proton
to the rescue.
( chuckles )
I'll explain later.
TUVOK:
The vortex is in visual range.
JANEWAY:
Time to intercept.
Forty-seven seconds.
Steady as she goes.
Keep laying down fire.
( grunts )
Direct hit! Starboard nacelle!
Both engines are off-line!
We're riding on inertia.
One more hit
and we're dead in the water.
Without warp drive, we'll never
outrun the shock wave.
Tuvok, can you reinforce
the aft shields
with our main deflector?
I believe so.
JANEWAY: Do it.
We're going to ride
that shock wave out of here,
let it push us
to the other side.
Adjusting shield harmonics.
Captain...
...they intend to block
our path.
Twenty seconds.
CHAKOTAY:
Prepare to fire.
That may not be necessary.
( dramatic theme playing )
The freighter is moving
to combat the aliens.
They're trying to distract
the Malon,
give us the upper hand.
Ten seconds.
The freighter's shields
are weakening.
Target their cargo hold.
Time to take out the garbage.
We're crossing the threshold.
Torpedoes.
Shock wave approaching.
600 meters.
Five hundred...
Four...
Aft shields at maximum.
All hands brace
for impact.
Pressure is building
on the outer hull.
Shields weakening.
( grunts )
( gasps )
We're clear.
The vortex
has been destroyed.
Are we out
of the Void?
Not yet.
That little maneuver
brought us up a bit short.
We're still 200,000 kilometers
from the boundary.
On screen.
Maintain course.
There.
What?
I saw something.
A star.
Remind me to check
your eyesight.
( console beeping )
Harry,
what do you see out there?
I see a densely-packed region
with thousands of star systems.
Looks pretty lively.
Full speed ahead.
( dramatic theme playing )