( soft theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
Seven of Nine.
How's my favorite
Borg today?
Annoyed. In the future,
you will announce
your presence
before entering
this room.
Sorry. I guess
I should have knocked first.
Are we ready to leave?
Yes. According to sensors,
spatial conditions are ripe.
A spontaneous protonebula
could emerge
within the next 20 minutes.
Mr. Paris is expecting us.
Hmm. Not a bad-looking
hologram.
( soft theme playing )
This should be exciting,
don't you think?
It's an astronomical survey,
nothing more.
What is your function
on this mission?
My function
is to study
the nebula's effects
on the crew.
We may be dealing with
new forms of radiation.
I can't wait to see one
of these clouds take shape.
I hear they're
quite beautiful.
I brought along
a holo-imaging device
to take a few snapshots.
This isn't shore leave.
There will be no time
for recreational activities.
The Borg-- party
poopers of the galaxy.
Tomorrow, we'll start you
on a new social exercise--
developing your joie de vivre.
( majestic theme playing )
( computers beeping )
Sorry about that.
Just a little
spatial turbulence--
nothing to worry about.
Oh!
Hello there.
I don't know about you,
but I've got a case
of class-2 claustrophobia.
Ah, I remember it well.
Lieutenant?
Oh, that's
what Starfleet cadets
used to call
these class-2 shuttles--
fast, maneuverable...
but not built for comfort.
PARIS:
They used to shoehorn
half a dozen cadets
into one of these things
for weeks at a time.
You did not want
to be around
when they opened
up that airlock.
Perhaps you should design
a new shuttle--
larger, more efficient.
Not a bad idea.
( dramatic theme playing )
I'm reading plasma surges
off the port bow.
All stop.
Keep our distance.
Seven, move over
by the helm.
I want to get a group shot.
I'm busy.
And smile like I know you can.
( rumbling )
What was that?
Another plasma surge.
It's massive.
Tom, back us off.
We're caught
in the gravimetric shear.
Engines are down.
We're receiving a distress call
from the away team.
They've been engulfed
in the shear line of the nebula.
Full impulse.
Bridge to
Transporter Room 1.
Stand by for
emergency beam-out.
I've got a partial lock on them,
but unless the shuttle
clears that nebula--
It won't. They've
lost propulsion.
Then it's going
to be a rough transport.
Energize.
I'm having trouble
separating their patterns.
Reset the
pattern buffers.
The signals are clearing.
Everyone all right?
( suspenseful theme playing )
My emitter-- it's been damaged.
I'll transfer
your program
back to Sickbay.
Hang on.
DOCTOR:
Sickbay to Transporter
Room 1. Report.
It looks like
some of your emitter circuits
were fused during transport.
Can you repair it?
B'ELANNA:
Most likely. I'll need
to run a diagnostic.
Most likely?
Relax, doctor. I'll keep
you posted. Mulcahey?
( suspenseful theme playing )
Computer, run
diagnostic routine Alpha-3-6.
COMPUTER:
Diagnostic in progress.
First thing in the morning,
I want you to check the results.
I'll be here bright and early.
( suspenseful theme swelling )
( majestic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
This protonebula seems to have
a mind of its own.
It's still expanding,
with no end in sight.
We're holding at a safe
distance to monitor its growth.
Rise and shine,
Lieutenant.
( groaning )
It's 0600 hours.
Early bird gets the gagh.
( clapping )
What do you want?
"Good morning" would be nice,
but I'd settle
for my mobile emitter.
Do we have an ETA
on those repairs?
( groaning ):
Go away.
Can't you at least
give me a prognosis?
( sighs )
The one day I get to sleep in...
You're worried about a few more
seconds of unconsciousness?
My freedom is at stake.
Computer, activate sonic shower.
One more thing,
Lieutenant.
I was thinking.
Hey!
I'm a doctor,
not a Peeping Tom.
It's nothing I
haven't seen before.
I was thinking,
if you brought the emitter
to Sickbay,
we could work on it together.
I have prepared a...
Hello? B'Elanna?
( suspenseful theme playing )
COMPUTER:
Regeneration cycle incomplete.
Commander.
How'd you sleep?
Well enough.
What's new?
That nebula's expanding
at a rate of 8,000
cubic kilometers per hour.
I've had to adjust course
11 times.
Sounds like you're
enjoying the big chair.
It's not a bad way
to spend the night.
I hear you've been doing
a fine job.
The crew's impressed.
Is it true you make them
call you "Captain Kim"?
Sir?
Good morning.
That remains to be seen.
Problem?
The proximity transceiver
in my cranial implant
has been activated.
That could indicate
a Borg presence nearby.
Harry?
I've been running
sensor sweeps all night.
I haven't
seen anything.
Perhaps the nebula
is masking a vessel.
No, not a chance.
A ship wouldn't last
ten seconds in there--
not even
a Borg cube.
Maybe it's a false alarm.
Your transceiver
could be malfunctioning.
It is possible.
Why don't you pay a visit
to Sickbay?
In the meantime, we'll redouble
our scans, just to be sure.
Very well.
I'll get the
scans underway.
If you don't mind
being an ensign again.
( slow theme playing )
( laughs )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( grunts )
Seven?
My proximity transceiver
activated again.
Looks like someone's
rerouting power
from the warp conduits.
To where?
Deck 8, Section 22,
the science lab.
Bridge to science lab.
Ensign Mulcahey, respond.
Harry.
( console beeping insistently )
Sensors are being deflected
by some kind of force field.
Commander, the force field
has a Borg signature.
Red Alert.
Captain to the Bridge.
Tuvok, take a security team
to the science lab.
Chakotay to Seven of Nine.
It looks like you were right.
We've detected Borg on
the ship-- Deck 8, science lab.
How many drones?
Unknown.
Tuvok's headed there now.
I will join him.
The science lab?
My mobile emitter's in there.
( dramatic theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
This technology resembles
a Borg maturation chamber,
but many of the components
are unfamiliar.
MALE:
Commander!
He was punctured by
an extraction tubule.
It removed a tissue sample.
There are residual nanoprobes
surrounding the wound.
Their encoding sequences
are identical to my own.
Your nanoprobes? How?
I don't know.
Take him to Sickbay.
( men grunting )
What are you doing?
I will be recognized
as Borg.
( suspenseful theme playing )
A drone...
but unlike any
I've ever seen.
It appears to be
in the fetal stage.
I don't understand.
The Borg assimilate.
They do not reproduce
in this fashion.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( liquid bubbling,
equipment humming )
( muted ):
Where did it come from?
I believe it was created here
in the science lab.
When the away team
beamed back to Voyager,
there was a transporter
malfunction.
Our patterns merged briefly.
It is possible that
some of my nanoprobes
infected the doctor's
mobile emitter.
They began to assimilate.
Yes.
Nanoprobes are encoded
to utilize any technology
they encounter.
Once it assimilated
the emitter, it began
to transform this
diagnostic station.
When Ensign Mulcahey
entered the room,
they sampled his DNA.
Using his genetic code
as a template
to create a life-form.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The drone has
increased in mass
by 17 percent.
SEVEN:
Its maturation rate
is 25 times
that of
a conventional Borg.
Tuvok, erect a level-10
force field around
this section.
Post round-the-clock
security.
You intend
to let it mature?
The alternative is
to pull the plug,
and I'm not prepared
to do that--
not unless I have to.
Resume your analysis.
I want to know
exactly what we're
dealing with here.
Or should I say whom?
Yes, Captain.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I've adapted
the astrometric sensors
to penetrate
the Borg force field.
I thought you said
this thing was a fetus.
An hour ago, it was.
The drone has entered
the fourth phase of gestation.
In human terms, it is
a child of six years.
DOCTOR:
You mean a boy
of six years.
From what I can tell,
the drone is male.
Seven, route your sensor data
to Sickbay.
I want to run
a few medical scans.
Stand by.
Well, he appears to be human
for the most part.
Borg implants
comprise approximately
27 percent of his body.
Curious.
His body plating is composed
of poly-deutonic alloy.
Just like my mobile emitter.
The nanoprobes must have
extrapolated that technology.
It could explain
his unique design.
Wait a second.
The doctor's emitter came
from the 29th century.
It's 500 years more advanced
than anything we've got.
It is logical to assume
this drone
will be equally advanced.
A 29th-century Borg.
In essence.
I've located my mobile emitter.
It's embedded
in his cerebral cortex.
The emitter has been
adapted to function
as part of his
central nervous system.
It controls
all autonomic functions.
That means
we can't remove it...
not without killing the drone.
Has it contacted
the Borg collective?
No. I have dampened
its proximity transceiver.
For now.
What about
when it grows up?
( suspenseful theme fades )
( sighs )
Reactive body armor?
Multidimensional adaptability?
Internal transporter nodes?
The drone possesses
superior technology.
It will fully mature
in less than two hours.
However, its Borg shielding
is not yet active.
We can still terminate it,
but we must act quickly.
Hold on a minute, Seven.
I want some answers first.
What normally happens
when a drone
disengages from the
maturation chamber?
It awaits instructions
from the collective.
So without those instructions,
it has no designation, right?
No purpose.
Correct.
If we can keep him
from interfacing
with the collective,
maybe we can give
him a purpose.
Captain...
This is the most
advanced drone
ever to exist.
We could teach him
our values, Seven.
Ah.
We could show him what it
means to be an individual.
If we fail...
if the drone were
to be assimilated,
the collective would
become far more powerful.
What I'm proposing is
the only defense we have
against that possibility,
short of murder,
and that's an order
I'd prefer not to give.
As I recall, Seven,
there were a few crew members
who had similar doubts
about you.
The situation is different.
Is it? A Borg?
Disconnected from
the collective?
Unsure of its identity.
A potential threat.
But we succeeded.
We're going to pull
the same trick again.
Only this time, you're
going to be the teacher.
I am to instruct the drone
in the ways of humanity.
Think of it as
first contact...
and you are our ambassador.
( soft theme playing )
Maturation cycle is complete.
( equipment powers down )
We are Borg.
State our designation.
Designation is irrelevant.
You are not part
of the collective.
You are an individual.
You will receive
your instructions from me.
Insufficient.
You must comply.
We are Borg.
My designation is Seven of Nine,
Tertiary Adjunct of
Unimatrix Zero One.
But you may call me
Seven of Nine.
You will comply
with my commands.
Seven of Nine.
Yes.
We are not Borg.
We are individuals.
Do you understand?
State our designation.
Apparently not.
The drone's responses
are programmed.
It doesn't understand
what I'm saying.
I must initiate
a direct neural interface.
Are you sure that's wise?
There is no other way
for me to communicate with it.
Proceed.
You will not be harmed.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Resistance is futile.
I am providing it
with instructions.
It understands.
( grunts )
The drone is probing
my neural pathways.
It is trying to assimilate
all of my knowledge.
I cannot disengage
the link.
Terminate interface!
You must comply.
You are hurting me.
( gasping )
I will comply.
Daily Log, Seven of Nine.
I've activated the drone's
linguistic database.
It is now capable
of assimilating information.
A direct neural link
is too dangerous.
So I've decided to use
Borg data nodes.
Special delivery--
two Borg data nodes.
More?
Link them to the data port.
How many Borg hitchhikers
are we going to pick up
on this trip?
Maybe this is
the collective's new strategy.
They don't
assimilate anymore.
They just show up
and look helpless.
Now, B'Elanna...
We don't know what
this drone will turn into.
It's gone from infant
to adult in one day.
It will become what
we help it to become.
How Starfleet of you.
Seven of Nine to Neelix.
Neelix here.
Report to the science lab
immediately.
Bring the first data node.
On my way.
( soft theme playing )
We are Borg.
State our designation.
I have compiled information
into this data node
for you to assimilate.
We do not understand.
You will, but first
you must assimilate this data.
Come here.
Comply.
Give me your arm.
Inject the data node
with an assimilation tubule--
this access port.
We do not
understand.
( sighs )
( soft theme playing )
Your designation
is Seven of Nine.
Yes.
Your designation is Neelix--
Talaxian.
That's me.
This is a laboratory
on a vessel.
The Starship Voyager.
I am traveling through
interstellar space.
Yes.
Why?
This is a ship
of exploration.
I am an explorer.
We all are.
We are Borg.
Well, no.
You are a unique individual,
one of many on Voyager.
This is not a Borg collective.
Do you understand?
Individual.
My thoughts are my own.
Precisely.
I wish to assimilate
more information.
Not yet.
Your neural pathways
require time
to process
the information.
You will need
to regenerate soon.
I will adapt
one of the alcoves
in our cargo bay
to your technology.
Take the drone to the doctor
for medical analysis.
Go with him.
All members
of this crew
must report
to the Sickbay
for evaluation.
( sighs )
When I am finished
here, I will join you.
( soft theme playing )
DRONE:
Duranium hull.
Plasma-based
power distribution.
Tricylic life-support
systems.
Artificial
gravity plating.
Oh, right on all counts.
Systems analysis
appears to be your forte.
You should think
about a future
in starship operations.
Human female.
Very good.
She was
frightened by me.
Why do you say that?
I detected an elevation
in her pheromonal response.
Well, you're new
around here.
An unfamiliar face takes
some getting used to.
I remember when I first
came aboard Voyager.
I provoked a few
strange reactions myself.
I still do
from time to time.
I mean, just look at me--
whiskers and spots.
Were people afraid
of you as well?
Well, no.
Do they fear me
because I am Borg?
Sometimes Borg can be
a little intimidating.
Don't take it personally.
I want to know more
about the collective.
You do?
Well, of course you do.
Tell me about the Borg.
Oh, what's to tell?
You've seen one cybernetically
enhanced species,
you've seen them all.
You'll have plenty of time
to learn all about them,
but first, you have
to give yourself a chance
to adapt to life
here on Voyager.
Now, Mister...?
Gosh, I'm sorry.
In all the excitement,
I forgot your name.
I do not have a name.
Well, every individual
needs a name.
We can't just run around
calling you "the drone."
That's not very
interesting, is it?
Seven of Nine
tells me
my designation
is irrelevant.
I disagree.
You should choose
a name for yourself,
something that defines
who you are.
After all,
there's only one of you.
One.
Oh, here we are-- Sickbay.
Good morning.
You are the Emergency
Medical Hologram.
And you are
very observant.
Step this way, please.
I have to get back
to Mess Hall.
There's nothing
to worry about.
The doctor is going
to run a few scans.
You'll be finished
before you know it.
I will comply.
It's a noninvasive
biomedical scan.
You won't feel a thing.
Your central nervous system
is functioning normally,
but I'm picking up
some degradation
in your neural pathways.
You'll need
to regenerate soon.
My central nervous
system is regulated
by your mobile emitter.
That's right.
Your mobile emitter
is more advanced
than these
diagnostic tools.
Far more advanced.
It's technology that came
from the 29th century,
400 years in the future.
I am an advanced
form of life.
Yes.
I am unique.
Mm-hmm.
Describe my origins.
Oh, it's a long story.
I wish to hear it.
Another time.
I wish to hear
the story now.
Mm.
In a nutshell, there was
a transporter malfunction.
My emitter fused with several
of Seven of Nine's...
nanoprobes.
I was an accident.
Call it "a random convergence
of technologies."
Am I unwelcome here?
On the contrary.
Our primary mission is to
explore new forms of life.
You may have been unexpected,
but, given time,
I am sure you'll make
a fine addition to the crew.
After all, you've got
my mobile emitter
driving your neocortex
so you're bound to make
a dazzling impression.
( chuckles )
That's called a joke.
Joke: A verbal
comment or gesture
designed
to provoke laughter.
I see you've got your
mother's sense of humor.
( majestic theme playing )
SEVEN:
Deck 11, Section 32,
Main Engineering.
That is the--
Warp core.
Fueled by a matter-
antimatter reaction,
which produces
a maximum output
of 4,000 teradynes
per second,
providing power for faster-
than-light propulsion.
Correct.
This isn't
a classroom, Seven.
Lieutenant B'Elanna Torres,
Chief Engineer--
Klingon-human hybrid.
She possesses
extensive knowledge
of this vessel's systems
as well as
a volatile temperament.
Volatile: English adjective
meaning "readily vaporizable
"at low temperature,
easily aroused,
tending
to violent eruption."
Very good.
You get a gold star.
Our presence here
is authorized.
The Captain asked me
to familiarize
the drone with Voyager.
Well, how about
familiarizing him
with the airponics bay?
I have got one hour
to come up with a way
to predict the expansion rate
of this protonebula
or Janeway's going to pull
the plug on the entire survey.
Unh. Do you mind?
If you apply
a multispatial algorithm,
it will accurately predict
the rate of expansion.
I can demonstrate.
All right.
( typing rapidly )
Amazing.
( soft theme playing )
Greetings.
Our designation...
My designation is One.
How are you today?
I'm just fine, thank you.
One?
He requested
a designation.
"One" seemed appropriate.
And how are you today, One?
Well. Thank you,
Captain Janeway.
Adapting to life
on Voyager?
Yes. To date I've assimilated
47 billion teraquads
of information
on a vast variety of subjects,
including particle physics,
comparative humanoid anatomy,
warp field theory...
and the culinary delights
of the Delta Quadrant.
Mr. Neelix. They've been
spending time together.
Is your assessment
of me complete?
Am I...sufficient?
( chuckling ):
Why, yes.
More than sufficient.
In fact, I'd say you were
making excellent progress,
but this isn't
an assessment, One.
I simply wanted to meet you.
With your permission,
I would like to be excused.
I've agreed to assist
Lieutenant Torres.
She wishes to increase
the efficiency
of the Bussard collectors.
Permission granted.
You've done a remarkable job.
Thank you.
Not only has he absorbed
an incredible amount of
knowledge in a matter of days,
but he seems to be
fitting in with the crew
and developing
a distinct personality.
He is adapting quickly.
Then why do I get the feeling
something's bothering you?
He has been expressing
curiosity about the Borg.
Ah...
and you're worried that
if he learns about them,
he may be drawn
to the collective.
Yes.
Maybe we should tell him
what he wants to know.
I'd rather he learn
about the Borg from us
than the collective.
The lure of perfection
is powerful, Captain.
He may be tempted
to seek out the Borg.
That would pose
a grave tactical risk.
Well, we can delay
telling him for now,
but keep in mind,
the drone is becoming
an individual.
Seven, he has
the right to know.
Sooner or later, we'll have
to answer his questions.
( soft theme playing )
Deck 8, Section 4,
Cargo Bay 2--
used for the storage
of spare components
and surplus materials.
It is also
where I regenerate.
You will reside here with me.
I wish to assimilate
more information.
You've assimilated
enough for one day.
You've also provided
invaluable assistance
to the Voyager crew.
You have exceeded
expectations.
Then expectations
were insufficient.
A simple "thank you"
would suffice.
Thank you?
A customary expression
of gratitude.
I paid you a compliment.
We must regenerate.
This technology
does not conform
with Starfleet
parameters.
Correct.
I am Borg.
This technology is Borg.
We must regenerate.
I wish to assimilate
all available data
pertaining to the Borg.
Step into the alcove.
No. You must face outward.
Computer, activate
regeneration cycle.
Alcoves beta and gamma.
Seven of Nine.
Yes.
Thank you.
( soft theme playing )
We must regenerate.
( beeping softly )
( suspenseful theme playing )
COLLECTIVE:
A Borg proximity signal
has been detected.
Origin:
Unimatrix 325, grid 006.
Alter course to intercept.
( soft theme playing )
Captain?
The drone transmitted
a Borg proximity signal.
Wake him.
You contacted
the collective.
No.
JANEWAY:
Check his transceiver.
You deactivated my transceiver
two days ago.
It appears your cranial
implants have adapted
and created
a secondary transceiver.
A Borg fail-safe device.
Precisely.
Have you detected
any vessels?
Long-range sensors
picked up a transwarp conduit.
A ship is approaching.
Time to intercept?
Approximately three hours.
The Borg?
Yes.
I wish to meet them.
Seven...
I think it's time
we showed our drone
what the Borg are all about.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The Borg have assimilated
thousands of species.
Correct.
What becomes
of those species?
Their neural pathways
are restructured
and linked to a single
collective mind--
the hive.
Their bodies
are augmented
with cybernetic
technology.
They become
drones.
I wish to experience
the hive mind.
If you did that,
you'd no longer be unique.
The Borg would destroy
your individuality.
And that is...
undesirable?
Very. The Borg are
the most destructive force
we've ever encountered.
They've assimilated
billions of individuals
against their will.
You were assimilated.
My link to the
collective was severed.
When you were
in the collective,
you assimilated others.
Yes.
You call the Borg
destructive.
Seven of Nine is not.
That's because she's regained
her individuality.
But if the Borg
had the chance,
they'd take it away
from her again.
They'd assimilate
everyone on Voyager.
With your
advanced technology...
the collective would become
even more destructive.
We have to prevent that
from happening,
but we can't do it
without you.
We need your abilities
to enhance our defenses.
Shields, weapons...
Will you help us resist them?
Seven of Nine...
do you wish to rejoin
the collective?
Voyager is my collective.
( soft theme playing )
ONE:
I will need time
to assimilate this information.
( alarm beeping )
CHAKOTAY:
All hands to battle stations.
A Borg vessel is approaching.
We just ran out of time.
Seven of Nine,
I'm detecting irregularities
in my autonomic
nervous system--
cardiovascular excitation,
vasoconstriction...
You're experiencing
an emotion-- anxiety.
It is only temporary.
Anxiety: A state
of apprehension caused by fear.
The Borg usually elicit
this response in others.
Are you experiencing
anxiety as well?
Yes. Along with every
crew member on Voyager.
Because they fear
assimilation?
Correct.
We are needed
on the Bridge.
Deck 1.
Seven of Nine.
Yes?
What will happen now?
We will engage the Borg.
Will Voyager be destroyed?
The Borg are powerful,
but Captain Janeway
is a resourceful leader.
We will resist.
Resistance is futile.
Perhaps.
( suspenseful theme swells )
The Borg vessel's
moving into range.
On screen.
Long-range tactical vessel.
Transwarp capability.
Ablative hull armor.
We're being scanned.
They're preparing
to attack.
You must help us
enhance our shields.
This station will give you
access to the shield generators.
They are hailing us.
Open a channel.
COLLECTIVE:
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
Resistance is futile.
I can hear them...
in my mind.
( rumbling )
They've locked on
a tractor beam.
The collective
is calling to me.
I hear it, too.
Billions of voices
speaking as one.
( suspenseful theme playing )
We must resist
that voice.
The crew of Voyager will be
destroyed if we don't.
Our shields are remodulating.
( dramatic theme playing )
We've broken free.
Can you enhance our phasers?
Yes.
Do it.
When he's finished,
target their propulsion system.
Be prepared to jump to warp,
Mr. Paris.
Enhancements complete.
You may fire.
What happened?
They inverted
our phaser beam
with a feedback pulse.
They just took out
our warp drive.
Your technology is limited.
I cannot enhance it further.
I must interface
with the collective.
I can disrupt their vessel
from within.
They will try to
assimilate you.
They will fail.
Harry, lock on to the drone.
That won't be necessary.
He's inside the sphere.
We are the Borg.
You will be assimilated.
My technology is superior.
Stop your attack
or I will destroy you.
Your technological
distinctiveness
will be added to our own.
Resistance is futile.
( console beeping insistently )
Shields down to 29 percent!
He's accessing
their navigational controls.
( dramatic theme playing )
It's heading directly
for the nebula.
If they get too close,
their hull will collapse.
COLLECTIVE:
Terminate your interface.
( rumbling stops )
Stand down Red Alert.
Tuvok, secure all stations.
Organize damage control
teams, Chakotay.
Captain,
I'm reading a life-sign
in the debris.
It's the drone.
He survived.
He's erected
a multispatial force field
around his body...
but it is weakening.
Get a lock on him.
Beam him to Sickbay.
Damage?
Several of his
implants were fused
in the explosion, but
they're regenerating.
His biological systems
are a different story.
Severe trauma to
the cerebral cortex,
internal bleeding.
He needs
immediate surgery.
The sphere?
Destroyed.
You were successful.
While I was linked
to the Borg,
I could hear
their thoughts...
their objectives.
They are aware
of my existence.
They will pursue me.
Irrelevant.
They will fail.
I need to get started.
No. I should not exist.
I was an accident--
a random convergence
of technologies.
You are unique.
I was never meant to be.
As long as I exist,
you are in danger.
All life on Voyager
is in danger.
We can talk about this later.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Allow the doctor
to proceed.
Lower the force field.
His synapses
are failing.
You must comply.
I will not.
Please.
You are hurting me.
You will adapt.
( gasping )
( melancholy theme playing )
I'm sorry.
( sniffles )
( majestic theme playing )