( suspenseful theme playing )
Higher.
Lieutenant, we're already
at 200,000 meters.
You could thermalize
at this altitude.
I said higher.
MAN:
We're at 300,000 meters.
Level us off.
Computer, disengage
safety protocols.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Disengaging safety protocols
presents
extreme risk of injury.
Override.
Acknowledged.
Safety protocols
have been disengaged.
Drop the force
field on my mark.
Aye.
Mark.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Torres.
I don't believe it.
Report to Engineering
on the double.
Computer, end program.
I was not aware
that protective attire
was required
for this mission.
I was on the holodeck--
orbital skydiving.
Leaping from a spacecraft
at exospheric altitudes.
A curious form of recreation.
The probe is
ready for launch.
However, there is
still a problem
with the telemetry link.
Lieutenant?
Is something wrong?
Actually, I'm not
feeling so well.
Can you handle the
launch without me?
You are putting me in charge?
Problem?
No. Just unexpected.
Shall I inform the doctor
you are ill?
No.
Don't.
( majestic theme playing )
Captain, someone's locked on to
our probe with a tractor beam.
CHAKOTAY:
It looks like a Malon freighter.
I had a feeling we hadn't
seen the last of them.
JANEWAY:
Open a channel.
KIM:
Aye, Captain.
Starship Voyager
to the Malon vessel.
That probe belongs to us.
Release it immediately.
No response.
Tom, how fast can
you get us there?
Ah. Two hours at least.
They'll be long gone.
If we instruct the probe
to emit a polaron burst,
it could disrupt
the tractor beam.
Do it.
The beam has been disabled.
JANEWAY:
Harry, redirect
the probe's course.
TUVOK:
The Malon are in pursuit.
That probe can't outrun them.
No.
But we might be able
to hide it from them.
Captain?
The probe surveyed
a class-6 gas giant
this morning.
I think we should send it
back for a closer look.
You're going
to steer the probe
into a gas giant.
TUVOK:
Captain...
the atmospheric pressure
will crush it.
Not if the Borg shielding
does its job.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Hail them again.
No response.
Voyager to Malon vessel.
Break off your pursuit.
The probe is entering
the giant's upper atmosphere
and the Malon vessel
is following it in.
( dramatic theme playing )
The probe's stuck
in a deep layer
of liquid hydrogen and methane
about 10,000 kilometers below
the outer atmosphere.
It's not responding
to commands.
Any good news?
It's still intact.
It can be repaired.
If we can get it
out of there.
Sorry I'm late.
We were just discussing how
to retrieve the probe.
Is there any possibility
of transporting it out?
No.
Just...no.
I don't see how
we could get close enough.
Is there any way
to boost transporter range?
Not in that kind
of atmosphere.
Well, if we can't
transport it out,
we'll just have
to fly in and grab it.
Perhaps you weren't
paying attention
when the Malon
freighter imploded.
( scoffs )
We won't be going
in a Malon freighter, Tuvok.
We'll be going
in our new shuttlecraft.
Ha. Oh, here we go again.
Let's face it-- class-2 shuttles
just don't cut it
in the Delta Quadrant.
We've needed something bigger
and better since we got here.
It's time we built it.
Tom, we've been through this
I don't know how many times.
We all appreciate
your enthusiasm...
Speak for yourself, Commander.
CHAKOTAY:
Bottom line--
we don't have time
to design and build
a ship from scratch.
I knew you were going
to say that.
So I've given us a head start.
Behold the Delta Flyer.
Ultra-aerodynamic contours,
retractable nacelles,
parametallic hull plating,
unimatrix shielding
based on
Tuvok's brilliant design
for the multispatial probe
and a Borg-inspired
weapon system.
The basic design
elements are...
adequate.
High praise.
If we used isomagnetic EPS
conduits in the plasma manifold,
we could maximize
the power distribution.
That's the spirit, Harry.
My shield designs could be
successfully applied
to a vessel of this size.
Big of you to admit it, Tuvok.
CHAKOTAY:
And you think
it'll be able to withstand
the gas giant's atmosphere.
The probe did.
I'm impressed.
But how quickly
can it be built?
We could replicate the alloys
and the new design components,
use spare parts
from storage.
If we worked around the clock,
we could have it up
and running inside a week.
I'm willing to put in
as much overtime as it takes.
I will forgo
regeneration
for the duration
of the project.
What about you, B'Elanna?
Building a new
vessel from scratch--
that's an engineer's
dream come true.
What do you say, Captain?
Why are you all
standing around?
( chuckles )
( soft theme playing )
Computer, add dynametric
tail fins to the nacelles.
Computer, delete
dynametric tail fins.
What'd you
do that for?
We are not designing
a "hot rod," Lieutenant.
PARIS:
That is exactly
what we're designing--
a 24th century,
warp-powered,
ultra-responsive
hot rod.
Your embellishments
are purely decorative.
They serve
no practical purpose.
No, I beg to differ.
If we make this thing
look mean enough,
other ships are going to think
twice before taking us on.
SEVEN:
I suggest we return
our attention
to the matter
of structural integrity.
Agreed.
SEVEN:
Lieutenant Torres'
hull design
is flawed.
We should be using
tetraburnium alloys
instead of titanium.
( clearing throat )
Uh, B'Elanna?
Sounds fine to me.
I'm going to finish up
the thruster specs.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( door chimes )
It's open.
Hey.
Thruster specs.
Thanks.
Where you running off to?
My quarters.
Stay a while.
I'll, uh, replicate some dinner,
a bottle of burgundy.
We deserve a break,
don't you think?
Not tonight.
B'Elanna...
what's going on?
Nothing.
Well, then
how come it's impossible
to have a conversation with you?
I'm sorry.
I don't want an apology.
I want an explanation.
Tom, I'm tired.
Asleep is more like it.
You hardly said three words
in that last meeting.
And then when Seven
changed your design,
you acted like...
like you didn't care.
I guess I didn't.
I don't get it.
How many times have we talked
about how great it would be
to do what we're doing now?
To really collaborate--
my piloting skills
and your engineering
expertise.
We finally get the chance
to create something
together from the ground up
and you're not the slightest
bit enthusiastic?
I'm doing my job, aren't I?
I delivered the thruster
specs on schedule.
B'Elanna, I'm not your boss.
I'm not questioning
your productivity
or keeping tabs
on how many hours you put in.
I just want to know
what's going on.
I have to go.
Computer, activate holodeck
program Torres 2-1-6.
COMPUTER:
The program is active.
Disengage safety protocols.
Warning.
Disengaging safety protocols
presents extreme
risk of injury.
Override.
Acknowledged.
Safety protocols
have been disengaged.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( growling )
( grunting )
( cries out )
( dramatic theme playing )
( yelling )
( straining grunt )
( coughing )
Ooh!
( B'Elanna panting )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Ensign, put us
into a high orbit.
I want to stay well-above
that ionospheric turbulence.
Aye, ma'am.
There's the probe.
10,000 kilometers
beneath all that methane
but still intact.
We're not alone.
I'm reading massive
theta radiation.
It's being dumped
by a Malon freighter
approaching from the far side
of the planet.
They're hailing.
Well, they're more talkative
than the last ones.
Open a channel.
KIM: Aye, sir.
Leave orbit of this planet now.
I don't believe
we've been introduced.
I'm Captain Janeway.
I know exactly who you are.
You are the person responsible
for the destruction
of one of our freighters
and the deaths
of nine Malon citizens.
I'm very sorry
that lives were lost,
but you're leaving out
an important detail.
Your people were trying
to steal a probe from us.
We warned them to stay away
from the gas giant,
but they didn't listen.
I'm taking your probe
as compensation for our losses.
That's going to be
a little difficult.
It's stuck
beneath the atmosphere
of the same gas giant
that crushed your other ship.
My people are expert
at salvage operations.
Well, Mr....
Vrelk. Controller Vrelk.
Vrelk.
We have a little expertise
of our own.
We're a very determined crew.
So my suggestion is
that you leave orbit
and in the future,
if you come across anything
that bears the insignia
of the USS Voyager,
head in the other direction.
You are making a serious error.
End transmission.
Why would people in the business
of toxic waste disposal
be so anxious
to get hold of a probe?
It's not just any probe.
It's multispatial technology.
Maybe they think it'll
help them find new places
to dump their garbage.
( gasping softly )
( clattering )
B'Elanna.
What a nice surprise.
I was just getting
ready to close.
Business has been slow
with so many people
busy on the new shuttle.
Oh.
I-I was just hoping
we could catch up.
You want to catch up?
W-with me?
If you have the time.
Are you kidding?
Yeah, we-- can I
get you something?
Name your poison.
Oh.
Um...
Come on, B'Elanna,
I handed that one to you
on a silver platter.
Huh?
Name your poison?
I was expecting one of those
scathing but affectionate
insults you always make
about my cooking.
Sorry.
You'll feel wittier
on a full stomach.
So, uh, what'll it be?
You know, actually...
I was hoping
for banana pancakes.
Huh. I-I-I don't think
I ever heard
of banana pancakes before.
My grandmother used to make them
for me when I was a kid.
It's always put a smile
on my face.
Well, then...
one smile coming right up.
Computer,
one stack of banana pancakes.
( sniffing )
Smells delicious.
Thanks.
So how have you been?
Oh, just great.
My security training
is going really well.
Tuvok told me the other day
that I'm, uh...
( clearing throat )
( imitating Tuvok ):
Not completely inept.
( normal voice ):
Aren't you going to try them?
Oh, sure.
Well?
Delicious.
I have to get back to work.
( slow theme playing )
( door opens, closes )
What are they still doing here?
Apparently,
they're not willing
to give up on the probe
so easily.
JANEWAY:
The question is:
How do they expect
to get their hands on it?
It's reasonable to assume
they're waiting for us
to retrieve the probe,
at which time, they'll
attempt to steal it again.
Maybe, but they have to know
we're prepared for that.
If they were planning
to fight, you'd think
they'd call in reinforcements,
try to outgun us.
Sensors don't show any other
Malon ships in the area.
Seven of Nine to the Captain.
Janeway here.
Report to the Astrometrics Lab.
I have important information
regarding the Malon vessel.
Tuvok?
What have you got?
I've been using
coherent neutrino beams
to document activity aboard
the Malon freighter.
In other words,
you've been spying on them.
I've made
a troubling discovery.
This is
a polythermal image
of an interior section
of the alien ship.
The shaded figures you see
are Malon crew members.
That appears to be
a small ship.
Correct. The Malon
are constructing
a spacecraft
composed of
tetraburnium alloys.
Theoretically, such a ship
would be capable
of withstanding extreme
atmospheric pressures.
I'll be damned.
They're going after
the probe themselves.
That's not
all, Captain.
According to
my projections,
they will finish
construction
of their vessel
at least 36 hours
before we finish ours.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Well, then...
I'd say we've got
an old-fashioned space race
on our hands.
( suspenseful theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've stepped up the pace
of construction
in order to finish our shuttle
before the Malon
finish theirs.
According to Seven's
most recent intelligence,
we've gained some ground
over the last 24 hours,
putting us in a virtual dead
heat with our competitors.
I keep telling you
we've got to reinforce
the hull with kellinite.
That's all there is to it.
Proposing the same flawed
strategy over and over again
will not make it
more effective, Ensign.
Well, we've got
to come up with something
or we'll never get this thing
off the ground.
( high-pitched whine )
Vorik, turn that damn thing off.
I can't hear myself think.
Sorry, sir.
PARIS:
Look, we could spend
weeks trying to solve this,
but we've got a ticking clock.
Engines are working.
Weapon systems are on line.
I say we launch now
and hope for the best.
Mr. Paris, that is perhaps
the most illogical statement
you've ever made.
Unless we find a way
to reconfigure
the structural integrity field,
the hull will incur
microfractures during descent.
PARIS:
Microfractures, Tuvok.
Doesn't necessarily mean
we'll have a hull breach.
TUVOK:
And if we do, I suppose
these useless design
elements from your
"Captain Proton" scenario
will compensate
for the problem.
Hey, every one
of these knobs
and levers is fully functional.
And completely
superfluous.
Maybe to you. I am
tired of tapping panels.
For once, I
want controls
that let me actually feel
the ship I'm piloting.
Where you going?
Holodeck.
What for?
To find out if this
microfracture problem
is a fatal flaw.
( soft theme playing )
Computer,
activate immersion shielding.
COMPUTER:
Immersion shielding activated.
Commence descent sequence.
Range to probe--
30,000 kilometers. 25,000.
Warning.
Atmospheric pressure
is exceeding tolerance levels.
Rapid ascent recommended.
Continue descent.
Acknowledged. Range to probe--
10,000 kilometers.
Disengage safety protocols.
Warning.
Disengaging safety protocols
presents extreme
risk of injury.
Override.
Acknowledged.
Safety protocols
have been disengaged.
Warning. Atmospheric pressure
is exceeding tolerance levels.
Reroute power
from secondary systems
to structural integrity.
Acknowledged.
Microfractures are present
in zones one and four.
( grunts )
( dramatic theme playing )
The Malon are venting
a theta radiation cloud.
Our shields are
down to 89 percent.
Ensign, back us off.
Vrelk is hailing.
( sighs )
On screen.
That was rude, wasn't it?
But we still have quite a bit
of antimatter waste to expel.
I hope we didn't
damage your shields.
Our shields are fine.
Mmm. Well, we only ejected
a small amount of waste
this time.
We still have much, much more
to get rid of.
Your shields
may not be able to stand
even higher levels
of theta radiation.
I've already told you
we're not going anywhere.
Let's stop playing these games,
Captain.
You've scanned my ship.
I've scanned yours.
We each know
the other is building a vessel
to retrieve the probe.
What you don't know is that my
vessel will be ready to launch
in less than two days.
You're too far behind.
Well, if you're so far ahead,
why bother
trying to scare us away?
Just trying to save you
the embarrassment of losing.
( disgusted grunt )
You think they're
really two days away?
He's probably bluffing,
but we're not going
to take any chances.
We've got to speed up
construction somehow.
We'd also better find a way
to shore up our shields
in case Vrelk decides
to do any more venting.
Good idea.
Janeway to
Lieutenant Torres.
Computer, locate
Lieutenant Torres
is in Holodeck 1.
Get down there.
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Hull microfractures are present
in zones one, two,
three and four.
Hull breach is imminent.
Repeat: Hull microfractures
are present in zones one,
two, three and four.
Hull breach is imminent.
Computer, freeze program.
( rumbling stops )
( suspenseful theme playing )
B'Elanna.
Chakotay to Sickbay.
Medical emergency.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What am I doing here?
You had an accident
on the holodeck.
How long was I out?
Almost 12 hours.
I'd better get back to work.
Not just yet.
Why?
The Captain's asked
me to keep you here.
But I feel fine.
( door opens )
Would you excuse us,
please, doctor?
Captain, what's going on?
When the doctor
examined you...
he found evidence
of internal bleeding,
fractured vertebrae,
contusions,
cranial trauma.
I guess the accident
was pretty serious.
The injuries
I'm talking about
didn't happen recently.
Some of them are weeks,
even months old.
Well, I'm an engineer.
I've had my share
of bumps and bruises.
But you didn't seek
treatment for any of these.
I don't run to Sickbay
every time I stub my toe.
Some of these injuries were
life-threatening, B'Elanna.
Do I look like I'm dying?
The doctor says many of
the wounds were treated...
by someone with the
medical expertise
of a first-year
nursing student.
( exhales sharply )
Oh, that's ridiculous.
Is it?
We investigated
today's accident.
You turned off
the safety protocols
during the holo-simulation.
Why?
We have
a microfracture problem.
With the safety protocols on,
there's no way to be sure
what would happen
during a real flight.
You don't really expect me
to believe that, do you?
Are you calling me a liar?
According to the holodeck logs,
you've been spending
a lot of time there
over the last few months.
If I were to check...
would I find
that you've been running
other programs
without safety protocols?
Would you like to look
at my personal logs as well?
B'Elanna, I'm
worried about you.
If there's something
wrong, I want to help.
Nothing's wrong.
Okay?
No. It's not okay.
And until you decide
to be more forthcoming,
you'll remain
under the doctor's supervision,
which means
you're off the shuttle project.
I'm sorry.
I'm not.
Now I know there's
something wrong.
( soft theme playing )
Engines are operating at close
to 90 percent efficiency.
Seven's got her new
weapon system on line,
and if we can just solve
that microfracture problem,
we'll be ready to go.
Keep on it.
Now...
let's talk about B'Elanna.
Tom, you had no idea
about these injuries
or how she got them?
She never complained
about being hurt.
But then again,
she's barely speaking
to me lately.
It's almost as if she's been
intentionally trying
to hurt herself.
You think all these injuries
have been happening
on the holodeck?
Well, where else?
If they'd happened
while she was working
as she claims, somebody would've
filed an injury report.
Any idea what sort of programs
she's been running?
You're thinking
the same thing I am.
( sighs )
I hate to go digging around
in someone's personal
holodeck programs,
but if she won't tell us
what's going on
I don't think
we have much choice.
Tom, what do you think?
He's right.
Start digging.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( door chimes )
( door chiming )
I'm sleeping.
Oh.
Hi.
( scoffs )
I-I thought you were the doctor
making a house call.
He let you
out of the cell block, huh?
( sighs )
He thinks familiar surroundings
will help speed my recovery.
Recovery from what?
That's what I said.
He thinks I'm suffering
from clinical depression.
Are you depressed?
What are you,
the new Ship's Counselor?
( sighs )
No.
Just a friend.
This whole thing
is so ridiculous.
I don't report a few scrapes,
and suddenly Janeway thinks
there's something wrong with me.
( scoffs )
Typical Starfleet, huh?
You have been running
holodeck programs
without safety protocols.
A few.
But I haven't put
anybody else at risk,
and it's nothing
that I can't handle.
Tell you what.
What do you say you and I pay
a little visit to the holodeck?
You can show me
some of the programs
you've been running.
Right now?
Sure. Maybe if I see
what you've been up to,
I can convince the Captain
there's nothing to worry about.
Heh. She's taken away
my holodeck privileges.
Consider them restored.
( soft theme playing )
Computer, activate holoprogram
Torres Zeta-1.
COMPUTER:
Program activated.
What are you doing?
What...? Aah.
( grunting )
( weapon firing )
( voice screaming )
Computer,
freeze program.
belay that command!
( grunting
and gasping )
( dramatic theme playing )
Turn it off!
Not until you tell me
what it is.
You know what it is!
Who's this?
Li Paz.
Don't you
recognize him?
Oh, I recognize them all.
Meyer. Nelson. Sahreen.
You created a program
to watch all our Maquis friends
get slaughtered.
What I want to know is why.
I thought we came
down here to talk
about safety protocols.
This has nothing
to do with that.
I'm not so sure.
The logs show you only ran
this program for 47 seconds--
the day after I gave you
the news about the massacre.
Then you shut it down
and started running
the most dangerous programs
you could find
with the safeties off.
Why?
This is ridiculous.
I'm leaving.
Computer,
seal the doors.
You can't do this!
The hell I can't.
You're not going anywhere until
you tell me what's going on.
( suspenseful theme playing )
B'Elanna...
why are you intentionally
trying to hurt yourself?
I don't know.
Are you trying
to commit suicide?
( exhales sharply )
No.
Then why?
Because... Ah.
Because if I sprain my ankle,
at least I feel something.
What do you mean?
Heh. I'm not trying
to kill myself.
I'm trying to see
if I'm still alive.
I don't understand.
( explosions and voices
grunting in distance )
When you look
at those corpses...
how do you feel?
( sighs )
Sad.
Angry.
Maybe a little guilty that I
wasn't there to die with them.
Not me.
I don't feel anything at all.
B'Elanna, the Maquis
were like our adopted family.
I can understand you trying to
block out that kind of pain--
You don't understand.
It's not just the pain.
I don't feel anything--
not about my
dead friends,
not about Tom...
you, my job.
Maybe you're afraid
if you let yourself
start to feel something,
you might not be able to stop.
You can't just shut off
your emotions, B'Elanna.
Sooner or later...
you're gonna have
to let yourself grieve.
Why?
Just so I can go through it
all over again?
What are you talking about?
When I was six,
my father walked out on me.
When I was 19,
I got kicked out of Starfleet.
A few years later, I got
separated from the Maquis.
And just when I
start to feel safe,
you tell me that all
of our old friends
have been slaughtered.
The way I figure it, I've lost
every family I've ever had.
B'Elanna...
you have a new family now...
here on Voyager,
and you're not going to lose us.
You're stuck with us.
You can't promise me that.
No, I suppose I can't.
Losing people is inevitable,
and sometimes it happens
sooner than we expect...
but I can promise you
that the people on this ship
aren't about to let you
stop living your life
or break your neck
on the holodeck.
You're going to have to find
another way to deal with this.
I don't know how.
Then we'll figure it out...
together.
( soft theme playing )
( rumbling )
JANEWAY:
Commander Chakotay,
we're under attack.
Report to the Bridge
immediately.
You'd better go.
( percussive theme playing )
( dramatic theme playing )
Why are they suddenly
picking a fight?
I believe they're attempting
to distract us, Commander,
while they launch
their new shuttlecraft.
( dramatic theme playing )
The Malon vessel
is 42,000 kilometers
from the probe and closing.
We can still
catch them.
Bridge to Lieutenant Paris.
Paris here.
JANEWAY:
We've got to launch now
if we're going
to get to the probe first.
Are you ready?
Yes, ma'am.
I'll begin
the prelaunch sequence.
What about
the microfracture problem?
We're keeping an eye on it,
but we sure could use
an extra hand.
Chakotay's on his way.
Chakotay...
let me go.
B'Elanna, I'm in a hurry.
I am not out to
get myself hurt
if that's what
you're thinking.
I just want to do my job.
I thought you weren't interested
in your job anymore.
If that hull breaches,
I should be there.
I'm still the best
engineer we've got.
Not lately.
I can do this.
I need to do this.
Forty seconds to launch.
Powering impulse engines.
Stand by to bring aft thrusters
on line.
( door opening )
B'Elanna.
I heard you might
need some help
keeping this thing
from falling apart.
Welcome aboard.
Vorik, you're in my seat.
Excuse me,
Lieutenant.
Twenty seconds to launch.
Get that hatch closed.
Hatch sealed.
Give me aft thrusters.
Aft thrusters enabled.
Ten seconds.
All right.
Let's see what this baby can do.
Five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
( dramatic theme playing )
The Delta Flyer is away,
Captain.
How long till they overtake
the Malon shuttle?
TUVKOK:
At present velocity,
approximately
three minutes.
( dramatic theme playing )
( rumbling )
We're in.
B'ELANNA:
Structural integrity's
at 92 percent.
KIM:
There's the Malon shuttle,
200 kilometers
off the port bow
and 3,000 kilometers
from the probe.
We'll catch them.
B'Elanna, how's the hull?
Structural integrity's down
about 12 percent.
( dramatic theme playing )
They're launching
spatial charges.
Shields holding.
They want to play dirty.
Let's show them
what a little
Borg-inspired weaponry
can do.
Acknowledged.
Loading
photonic missiles.
We've lost power
to secondary systems.
Fire.
Three direct hits.
They're losing
attitude control.
They're pulling up.
Nice shooting, Seven.
I'm taking us
down to the target.
Harry, get ready
to grab the probe.
Still out of
transport range.
We're losing integrity.
50 percent...
forty...
If you can hold us together
for another half a minute,
we'll be within range
of the target.
We still need
to survive the ascent.
One thing at a time.
We're losing
structural integrity.
It's down to 25 percent.
Harry, prepare to lock on.
We've got microfractures
forming-- aft starboard hull
zone two.
I've got a lock.
Beaming the probe
into the cargo hold.
Got it.
Initiating rapid ascent.
Harry, I need
those secondary systems
back on line.
I can't. They're fried.
( metal groaning )
( dramatic theme playing )
( grunting )
Lieutenant, what are you doing?
Patching a hole before it opens.
That'll never hold.
It'll hold a minute or two,
and with any luck,
that's all we need.
Seven, take over here.
I need an EPS relay.
Uh, there's one in the
transporter control circuitry.
The panel is sealed.
Good. Get away from it.
I need a phaser.
Watch out.
I don't know
if this is going to work.
( dramatic theme
continues playing )
Glad you decided to come along.
The Delta Flyer has docked.
And the Malon?
They're a little
preoccupied.
Seems their shuttlecraft's
having a problem
climbing out of the
gas giant's atmosphere.
Get us out of here, Ensign--
warp 2.
Aye, Captain.
( majestic theme playing )
B'Elanna.
I heard you did
a hell of a job.
So? How are you?
You mean am I back
to my old charming self?
I don't know.
( sighs )
Give it time.
Chakotay.
What you did
down in the holodeck today...
thanks.
But if you ever do anything
like that again,
I'll break your neck.
( chuckles )
( soft theme playing )
Computer...
one stack of banana pancakes
with maple syrup.
( chuckles softly )
( majestic theme playing )