( serene theme playing )
Welcome to Earth.
I am Admiral Bullock and I will
be your commanding officer
for the next six months.
Questions, comments--
bring them to me.
Problems--
talk to Lieutenant Kinis.
Larson...
you're assigned
to the Federation Counsel
Deputy Liaison Officer.
Young and Reiskin, report
to Orbital Flight Control.
You'll be monitoring incoming
vessels from the Bolian sector.
Report back
to your commanding officer
as soon as you've completed
your assignments.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( indistinct chattering )
( majestic theme playing )
I can save you
some time there, son.
They're bamboo.
I know that.
Unfortunately, my tricorder
is reading them as maple trees.
I think the isodyne relays
must be malfunctioning.
Well, why don't you pay
a visit to Logistical Support?
Maybe they'll issue
you a new one.
Good idea.
I'm going
that way myself.
Mind some company?
Not at all.
So, what's your
assignment here?
I don't know.
I haven't received
my orders yet.
I just arrived.
From where?
A three-year tour
on the Intrepid.
Is that a fact?
I thought the Intrepid was
patrolling the Neutral Zone.
It is. I caught a transport
vessel at Deep Space 7.
Got tired of wrestling
with the Romulans?
Let's just say
it's good to be back.
What about yourself?
How long have you been
posted here, Mister...?
Boothby. Boothby
is the name.
Boothby, I've heard of you.
I should hope so.
I've been tending these
grounds for 54 years.
Give or take
a few months.
And beautiful
grounds they are.
Mm-hmm.
Logistical Support.
Straight through
the main complex,
second door
on your right.
Thank you.
Commander.
Logistics is a secure area.
They won't let you in
with that
holo-imaging device.
Fresh from
the Neutral Zone...
You're not a Romulan
double agent are you, son?
Actually, I was just
recording a few images
for my friends back home.
Would you mind
posing for a shot?
Me? You want a picture of me?
The one and only Boothby.
My friends would be impressed.
Well, when you
put it that way.
Cadet!
Take our picture,
will you?
Don't cut off our heads.
I expect a copy of that,
young man.
( sighs )
( suspenseful theme swells )
( jazz music playing
over speakers )
( people chattering )
You're in my seat.
And you're reading my book.
You want my drink, too?
Depends. What is it?
Klingon martini-- vermouth,
gin, with a dash of bloodwine.
Bloodwine-- never
touch the stuff.
What do you like?
Excuse me, I was
waiting for a friend.
Valerie Archer.
Hayek. Jason Hayek.
Nice tattoo.
I bet there's a story behind it.
Ha. A long one.
A Cave Beyond Logic:
Vulcan Perspectives
on Platonic Thought.
Sounds fascinating.
You can borrow it
if you like.
Thanks anyway.
I can only take
small doses
of Vulcan philosophy.
Stationed here?
Temporarily.
Where do you call home?
You first.
Where are you from?
Everywhere. My parents
were starship officers.
By the time I was ten,
I'd seen half the Quadrant.
Starfleet brat.
Bratty as they come.
( choking )
( dramatic theme playing )
Can I ask you a question?
Have you ever reverted?
Reverted?
Not yet.
Ensign O'Halloran, this is
his third time this week.
If it happens again, they'll
pull him out of training.
What about you?
Any trouble?
Oh, I can keep my human form.
It's the little things
that bother me.
Little things?
Breathing oxygen,
bipedal locomotion,
and sleeping--
the concept of being unconscious
for eight hours a night,
it's so...alien.
I know what you mean.
That's why I started
reading their books.
For some reason,
it helps me relax.
But we shouldn't be
talking about this.
Think human. Talk human.
Be human. Remember?
How could I forget?
So, had a chance
to take a look around?
Not yet.
Headquarters has
a lot more to offer
than conference rooms
and consoles...
if you have the right guide.
Is that an invitation?
I get off duty at 1900 hours.
TUVOK:
Commander.
Speak of the devil.
We were just discussing
Vulcan philosophy.
Join us.
Another time perhaps.
We have work to do.
Oh, can't it wait?
I'm afraid not.
What about tonight?
Do we have a date?
1900 hours--
meet you right here.
I'll do my best.
Live long and prosper.
A "date"?
Relax, Tuvok. I plan
on standing her up.
We agreed to limit our
investigation to surveillance.
It was worth the risk.
She talked
about training.
These are some kind of aliens
learning to pose as humans.
For what purpose?
I don't know.
I didn't get that far.
We're due back at the
transporter coordinates.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Excuse me! Gentlemen!
You've entered a restricted
area, captains and above.
Sorry, we didn't
realize--
I'm going to have
to ask you to come with me.
Why?
All unauthorized
personnel
are to be debriefed
by Starfleet Intelligence.
Direct orders
from Admiral Bullock.
Listen, Ensign, we're late for a
meeting with Starfleet Command.
The debriefing will
have to wait.
I'm sorry, Commander.
( chuckles )
Very well.
( grunts )
When he regains
consciousness,
he'll no doubt want
to report this incident.
Chakotay to Paris.
Three to beam up.
PARIS:
Three?
I'll explain later.
Who's that?
One of Starfleet's finest.
Take us to Voyager.
What did you find
down there?
Earth.
( suspenseful theme swells )
Welcome aboard.
Where am I?
On a starship.
What starship?
Why have you brought me here?
I'll be reporting this
incident to the Admiral.
You can drop the charade.
We know you're not human.
Who are you?
Gentry, David.
Rank: Ensign.
Starfleet service number
9-9-beta-3-2-7-8.
Planet of origin: Earth.
We're not interested in your
knowledge of human culture.
We're not part of
your re-creation.
I'm Captain Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
I'm from Earth.
You're not.
Gentry, David.
Rank: Ensign.
Starfleet Service Number
9-9-beta-3-2-7-8.
Doctor.
What are you doing?
I need a sample
of your DNA.
Why?
Since you won't
tell us who you are,
we have no choice but
to find out for ourselves.
You won't be harmed.
Gentry to Headquarters.
Security alert!
We've disabled
your combadge.
No!
Don't touch me.
Disease!
Humans!
( whining snarl )
( suspenseful theme playing )
It appears he's released
a cellular toxin
into his bloodstream.
He's dead.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Until we know
exactly what's going on,
I'm keeping Voyager concealed
behind a class-3 moon.
CHAKOTAY:
Federation Council,
Astrophysics,
Starfleet Medical Complex.
They even re-created
the officers' club--
the Quantum Cafe.
Computer, return
to time index 4228.
That's Boothby.
SEVEN: Captain?
The head groundskeeper
at Starfleet Academy.
When I was a cadet,
he used to give me fresh
roses for my quarters.
It's safe
to assume
this individual
is not Boothby.
Whoever they are,
they've gathered
incredibly accurate
information
about Starfleet
Headquarters.
Perhaps they had access
to a Federation database.
Or they've been
to San Francisco.
The habitat's
population consists
of humans, Vulcans,
Bolians, Ferengi...
All Alpha Quadrant
species.
What do we know
about this artificial
environment, Seven?
I've used the tricorder data
holo-images and
astrometric scans
to extrapolate a cross-section
of the interior.
I believe they used
a combination
of holographic projection
and particle synthesis.
Power source?
There are 13
thermionic generators
beneath the city.
I can't identify
the energy signatures.
The habitat's
heavily fortified.
They are well prepared
to defend against an attack.
DOCTOR: Sickbay to Captain.
Go ahead.
I've completed
my postmortem analysis.
You'd better get down here.
On my way.
If this is a training ground,
it could mean they're planning
an invasion of the Federation.
We should prepare for the worst.
See if you can find a way
to penetrate their defenses.
( suspenseful theme playing )
DOCTOR:
He may look human,
he may sound human,
he may even smell human,
but there's no question--
he's alien.
Was he genetically
altered?
On a highly
sophisticated level.
If it weren't
for microcellular scans,
I wouldn't be able
to distinguish him
from the genuine article.
I've managed to isolate
the alien DNA.
Fortunately, most of his cells
are still chemically active.
If I use
a cytokinetic injection,
I should be able to trigger
a genetic reversion.
Do it.
( rippling )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Talk about a wolf
in sheep's clothing.
Species 8472.
The question is:
Why are they training
to pose as human beings?
Back in
the 20th century,
the Soviets used
to build American towns
to train their agents to
infiltrate the United States.
Species 8472 could be doing
the same thing.
They're going
to infiltrate
the Alpha Quadrant.
Maybe they already have.
Tom's right. How
else could they
have gathered their
information about us?
Perhaps they acquired it
from the Borg.
It doesn't matter
how they got their data.
We need to find out
what they intend to do with it.
If our previous experience
is any indication,
they will try
to destroy Earth.
A logical assumption.
They did threaten to purge
our galaxy of all life.
Tuvok, keep working on a way
to target
their habitat's power source.
We're going to need nanoprobe
warheads and plenty of them.
Seven, see to it.
Yes, Captain.
In the meantime, I've
got a date to keep.
I made contact
with one of them--
Commander Valerie Archer.
Maybe I can capitalize
on the relationship,
get a better idea
of what they're planning.
Tom, Harry, take him back
in the Delta Flyer.
Keep a constant transporter
lock on him.
If Species 8472 attacks Earth...
the Federation won't have
any defenses against them,
and I don't need to remind you
that we have no way
to warn Starfleet Command.
Voyager may be the last defense
against an all-out invasion
of Earth.
( suspenseful theme swells )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Last minute preparations?
Just planning
my big night out.
I can recommend
a nice Japanese
replimat on
the Embarcadero.
I was never very good
with chopsticks.
Starfleet Headquarters.
Brings back memories
even if it is
just a re-creation.
I remember my
last visit there.
I was given my
general orders
for Voyager's
first mission--
proceed to the Badlands,
and find the Maquis.
The orders
that brought us together.
What about you?
When was the last time
you were at Headquarters?
Before today?
March 3, 2368--
the day I resigned
my commission.
I can still remember
the look on the Admiral's face.
Which one?
Namimby.
He taught at the
Academy, didn't he?
That's right.
Interspecies ethics,
wasn't it?
Tactical analysis.
Of course.
( sighs )
Kathryn, you think
I might be one of them.
You're testing me.
You and Tuvok were
in the alien habitat
for nearly three hours.
Anything could have
happened down there.
True.
Why don't you have Tuvok
meet us in Sickbay?
The doctor can perform
a microcellular analysis.
Tuvok's already there.
You could've just asked me
to report to Sickbay.
Given Ensign
Gentry's reaction,
I thought I'd be
a little more tactful.
You're not taking any
chances, are you?
Don't feel singled out.
I've asked the doctor
to examine the entire crew.
There's no telling
how 8472
got their information
about Starfleet--
from the Borg, Earth.
For all we know, there's
been an impostor on board.
Cell morphology normal.
All of your nucleotide
sequences
are accounted for.
You're 100 percent human.
That's a relief.
And Tuvok?
Green-blooded Vulcan
through and through.
Well, two down,
125 to go.
You'd better get going.
Right.
I don't want to be late.
Just be home
before midnight.
Yes, ma'am.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I've enhanced this tricorder
with a transoptic
datalink.
It should help you access
some of their systems.
Type-1 phaser, modified
to fire Borg nanoprobes.
Right.
Do you always arm yourself
before a first date?
You've never had a date
with Species 8472.
Personally, I don't go out
with girls from other galaxies.
You're a true
explorer, Chakotay.
Is she cute?
In her human form, anyway.
I've always wondered what it
would be like to date an alien.
I'll take notes.
We're making our approach.
All stop.
Shields up.
( suspenseful theme playing )
DOCTOR:
Feisty little fellows.
You've increased their cellular
motility by over 200 percent.
I thought
it would be prudent
to maximize
their efficiency.
Seven, the last time
we used nanoprobes,
we sent 8472 scurrying
back to fluidic space.
You can't get more
efficient than that.
The species
is highly adaptive.
It's been over a year
since our first encounter.
They may have developed
a defense
against our technology.
There's one way to find out.
We can test the nanoprobes
on our corpse.
You'll find the body
in Morgue Chamber 3.
Beam it to the surgical bay.
The creature's only been dead
for a few hours.
There should still be plenty
of cellular activity.
Initiate a bio-scan,
full spectrum.
Don't worry.
It's an autonomic reflex.
The creature
still has residual
bio-electric activity
in its nervous system.
Something's wrong.
The nanoprobes should
have taken effect by now.
Hmm.
What is it?
The creature's nucleotides
are still intact.
It looks like your concerns
were warranted.
We'll have to inform
the Captain.
We may have to--
Doctor.
Hmm. False alarm.
I will replicate
more nanoprobes.
I don't mind
telling you, Seven,
I'm still holding out
for a diplomatic
solution.
Improbable.
Species 8472 will not
respond to diplomacy.
Funny. We used to say the
same thing about the Borg. Ha.
My point is,
anything's possible
if you keep an open mind.
Optimism, Seven.
Try to look on
the bright side.
It is difficult
to be optimistic
when we are preparing
for battle.
Have you ever
heard the phrase
"the best defense
is a good offense"?
No.
Throughout human history,
weapons of mass destruction
were often designed
in the hopes that
they'd never be used.
And yet, in Earth's
third world war,
nuclear weapons accounted
for 600 million casualties.
Were they looking
on the bright side?
An unfortunate
exception.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( lounge music
playing over speakers )
We were just
talking about you.
Oh?
She didn't think
you were going to show up.
Boothby!
I've known Archer
since she was
a first-year cadet.
She's not easily impressed.
I didn't think
you were her type.
( chuckling )
Oh, uh,
if you'll excuse me,
I've got some midnight orchids
that need my attention.
Think about what I said,
young lady.
You'll be fine.
Thank you, Boothby.
Problems?
I was offered a field
commission this morning.
First Officer of
the Starship Hor-CHA.
Congratulations.
It's a Klingon vessel.
Oh.
So, what did Boothby say?
Du cha
mee gagh roch.
"Smile when you
eat the gagh."
( laughing )
Wise words.
Yeah.
Do you always seek advice
from the groundskeeper?
Half the captains
in Starfleet
wouldn't be where
they are today
if it weren't for Boothby.
Lopez, Picard,
Richardson...
just to name a few.
Closing time.
You offered to be my guide.
Where's our next stop?
Can you dance?
I've been accused of trying.
It's Pon farr Night
at the Vulcan nightclub.
Vulcan?
It's just
around the corner.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( chuckles )
Take it easy, Harry.
We didn't build
the Delta Flyer
to withstand
such extensive pacing.
He should have
contacted us by now.
Give him time.
Four hours?
It's a date.
These things
can't be rushed.
They probably
just finished dinner,
a couple of drinks,
and now, they are moving
past the polite stage.
"Polite stage."
The last 8472 I met
tried to dissolve me
from the inside out.
It was only trying to get
to know you better, Harry.
You can't fault
a person for that.
Look, Chakotay can
take care of himself
and if he can't,
who better than us
to come to the rescue?
( suspenseful theme playing )
Turns out the transporter
malfunctioned.
My uniform ended up
in the pattern buffer.
You're kidding.
You were naked?
Not entirely.
I had my combadge.
I hope it was
well-placed.
Computer, lights.
So this is where
they're putting up
officers nowadays.
Not bad.
Can I get you
something to drink?
Water's fine.
I'm beginning to think
you're a teetotaler.
I like to stay
in control.
Always at Yellow
Alert, huh?
Something like that.
Find anything interesting?
Beyond the Galactic Edge:
Humanity's Quest for Infinity.
This is
a 21st century edition
of Hesterman, isn't it?
Replicated.
Good book, though.
Never read it.
You should.
Human beings--
they're quite a paradox.
Oh? How so?
At first glance...
they're so primitive--
genetic impurities,
no telepathy, violent--
and yet they've created
so many beautiful ways
to communicate their ideas--
literature, art, music.
At times, I've actually enjoyed
being in this form.
You must think I'm crazy.
Not at all.
I wonder what they think
about us?
Hard to say.
I'll tell you
what I think.
They despise us.
They'll attack any species
that's not a part
of their Federation. Mmm.
Speaking of being
in human form,
I could use
an isomorphic injection.
You need one?
I'm fine.
Make yourself at home.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Commander.
How do you like the view?
Lovely.
Looks like a full moon.
You can see the entire bay
on a night like this.
I should have brought
my holo-imager.
You make
a pretty picture.
Mm, feel that?
Salinated oxygen molecules
stimulating the epidermal
neural receptors.
Non-fluidic space
has its charms.
No argument there.
Planet Earth.
The simulation will be
real soon enough.
How soon do you think?
Weeks, days.
As soon as they think
we're ready.
Can I be honest with you?
Please.
I'm starting to wonder if
all this is worth the effort.
What do you mean?
This simulation,
our mission--
are we certain
the humans pose a threat?
They were allies
with the Borg.
They invaded our realm.
That was one incident.
Doesn't mean
the entire Federation
is planning a war against us.
We can't trust them.
We have to prepare
for the worst.
I'm not so sure.
I think you've been
human a little too long.
Before you know it,
I'll be sending my résumé
to the real Starfleet.
Ha. "Alien from distant
galaxy seeks employment.
References available
upon request."
Well, it's getting late.
I'd better go.
Already?
I have a tactical report
to finish before morning.
Aren't we forgetting
something?
I'm no expert at
human dating rituals,
but I think it's customary
to kiss good night.
( slight chuckle )
You've never
done this before.
Actually...
Me, neither.
Just...think of it as
part of our training.
( sighs )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( beeping )
MALE:
Report.
I analyzed his DNA.
Your suspicions were correct.
How much does he know?
It's difficult to say.
He'll have to be interrogated.
Where is he?
By now, he should be
in the main quad.
I recommend we go to daylight.
He'll be easier to track.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Chakotay to Paris.
Delta Flyer, respond!
( grunts )
( dramatic theme playing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
( door chimes )
Yes, come in.
The Borg modifications
are complete.
Nineteen standard photon
torpedoes and three class-10s
armed with high-yield
warheads.
More.
We've depleted our supply
of nanoprobes.
Replicate a new supply.
That is not possible.
Have the doctor extract them
from your bloodstream,
grow them in a petri dish,
whatever it takes.
If we do engage 8472,
I don't intend to run out
of firepower mid-battle.
You of all people
should understand that.
They killed what--
four million drones?
Directive 010:
"Before engaging
alien species in battle,
any and all attempts
to make first contact
and achieve nonmilitary
resolution must be made."
In this case, we made first
contact over a year ago,
and we barely got
out of it alive.
It seems to me
a battle is inevitable.
Maybe even war.
So why can't I get that
directive out of my mind?
This species intends
to purge our galaxy of all life.
It's time you resisted
your Starfleet philosophy.
TUVOK:
Captain to the Bridge.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The away team
is hailing us.
Tom.
Chakotay's in trouble.
He tried to contact us
ten minutes ago,
but his signal
was cut off.
Some kind of force field
went up around the habitat.
We can't get a lock on him.
Has your vessel been detected?
I don't think so.
At least no one's tried
to take a shot at us yet.
Hold your position.
Keep trying to locate him.
We're on our way.
PARIS: Yes, ma'am.
Bring those Borg weapons
on line.
Red Alert.
All hands to battle stations.
Take us out of orbit.
( suspenseful theme fading )
I thought you had
a tactical report to finish.
What'll you
have, son?
I'm a single
malt man, myself.
Aged 200 years.
Been saving it
for a special occasion.
And I'd say this
is special enough, mm-hmm.
A toast...to Earth.
Ah.
Chakotay.
Rank: Commander.
Starfleet Service Number:
47-Alpha-6-1-2.
First Officer, USS Voyager.
Species 8472.
Origin: Fluidic space.
Well, now that we've
been formally introduced,
how many ships?
Cat got your tongue?
I asked you a question.
How many vessels do you
have in the Delta Quadrant?
One.
How did you find us?
We detected what looked like
a Federation subspace
transmission.
It took us weeks
to track it here.
We wanted this simulation
to be accurate
to the last detail.
We obviously went
a little too far.
Now that you know
about our re-creation,
you've no doubt alerted
the Federation.
Your fleet will
be on its way.
You've got it wrong.
We're not planning a war
against you.
Is that why you were here
to spy on us--
because you're curious?
MALE:
Sir?
A starship is approaching.
It's Voyager.
Raise our shields.
Stand by, all weapons.
Captain Janeway is not here
to launch an attack.
She's here to find me.
We've got
the real McCoy here.
We might as well take
advantage of it.
Perform a genetic
extraction.
It may help us
find a better way
to maintain these
human forms.
Yes, sir.
( suspenseful theme playing )
We're approaching
the habitat.
Shields to maximum.
Charge weapons.
All hands, this is the Bridge.
Tactical alert.
Report to your posts and
stand by to engage the enemy.
I have a visual.
We're being scanned.
Let them take a look.
SEVEN:
The Delta Flyer is
heading up from the habitat.
Open a channel.
Tom? Status.
They've taken a couple
of potshots at us, Captain.
We've lost our shields.
Mind if we join you?
You're clear to dock.
Shuttle Bay 2.
Any word from Chakotay?
I'm afraid not.
Bring us within range.
Target their weapons array.
Captain, we should target
their power systems as well.
No, I don't wanna risk shutting
down their life support.
If we can end this
without casualties,
so much the better.
This species does not
deserve our compassion.
You picked a lousy time
for an ethical debate.
The weapons array now.
We're entering range.
3,800 kilometers.
3,500.
3,200.
CHAKOTAY:
Valerie.
That's not my name.
Then what is it?
You're afraid of us,
aren't you?
You think we're violent.
That we're planning
to destroy your species.
But none
of that's true.
If you would
take the time
to speak to us directly,
we could prove it to you.
"There are no secrets except the
secrets that keep themselves."
Shaw.
George Bernard Shaw.
I saw a copy of his collected
works on your bookshelf.
He had a complex mind...
for a human.
And he had a point.
As long as we keep spying
on each other,
making assumptions,
we probably will go to war.
( alarm blaring )
Voyager.
( suspenseful theme playing )
They're charging weapons.
Do the same.
We're being hailed.
Mr. Boothby.
Captain Janeway.
Good to see you
after all these years.
Enjoying
the Delta Quadrant?
Don't get sassy with me,
young lady.
This re-creation
may be Starfleet,
but our weapons are
far more sophisticated.
I can destroy your vessel
with a single command.
Run along, now.
I'm not going anywhere.
Not until you return
my First Officer
and give me a damn
good explanation
for what you're doing
in our galaxy.
I've targeted your re-creation
with Borg nanoprobes.
And we're willing to use them
if you force us to.
Don't try to rattle my cage.
I'll disable your tactical
systems before you--
The last time
our species engaged in battle,
you suffered heavy casualties.
Are you willing to take
that chance again?
An armed conflict
isn't going to solve
our problems.
We could go on making threats.
Spying on each other.
Risking a war
between our species.
Or we could try
a more direct approach.
What do you have in mind?
How about a class reunion?
Targ manure!
United Federation of Planets...
tolerance for all species...
the Prime
Directive...
targ manure,
every word of it.
Your metaphor is colorful,
but inaccurate.
Vulcan logic...
add that
to the list.
Obviously, you've studied
a Starfleet database.
You must've learned something
about our history.
We adhere to
our directives.
High-minded ideals
are one thing,
but your actions tell
a very different story.
You infiltrated
our re-creation,
captured and killed
one of our people.
I told you he
took his own life.
You created biological weapons
to infect our species.
You are allies with the Borg.
No.
There's a drone sitting
at this very table.
Look at her-- all gussied up
to look like a human being.
I am no longer part
of the Collective.
Once a Borg, always a Borg.
Seven of Nine is
a member of this crew.
The Borg are irrelevant.
It's the humans
that pose a threat.
They think
the Federation
is a hostile
invasion force
out to destroy
their species.
I see.
So you're planning a preemptive
strike against Earth.
Maybe I am.
You realize
I can't let that happen.
Go ahead.
Fire your damn nanoprobes,
blow our re-creation
to high heavens.
There are a dozen more
scattered throughout
the Quadrant.
You'll never find them all.
What if I told you
that Starfleet
isn't planning an invasion,
that no one on Earth
has even heard of you?
I'd say you're lying.
Have another look at that
Federation database of yours.
You'll see there's no mention
of your realm.
BULLOCK:
Immaterial.
Any information
regarding our species
has no doubt been classified
by Starfleet
Intelligence.
Good point.
You know, we could
keep this paranoid
debate going all day.
You have
no reason to trust us,
and we have no
reason to trust you.
Hear, hear. I knew this reunion
would be a fiasco.
Admiral...
JANEWAY:
Seven...
disarm the warheads.
Captain?
Do it.
What are you trying
to prove, young lady?
One of us has to take
our finger off the trigger.
It might as well be me.
Their weapons
are off-line.
It's a trick.
Our defenses are down.
What will you do now?
Blow Voyager to high heavens
or do we keep talking?
Humans...you've got
a flair for the dramatic,
I'll give you that.
You want to keep talking?
Fine by me, but no more
beating around the bush.
Now what do you want from us?
The truth, Captain.
Voyager is alone
in the Delta Quadrant.
We haven't been in contact
with Earth for over four years.
Explain why
you attacked our realm,
hand in hand with the Borg.
At the time, we didn't realize
the Borg had started
the war against you.
We forged a temporary
alliance with them
because we thought
you were the threat.
"Your galaxy will be purged."
Sound familiar?
We were only trying
to defend ourselves.
If that's true,
why are you still in our galaxy?
Your conflict with the Borg
ended over a year ago.
Why re-create Starfleet,
masquerade as humans?
It looks to me like you're
the ones planning an invasion.
The truth.
Don't answer her.
She's manipulating us.
If you won't answer,
I will.
Commander!
Our mission is to
infiltrate your homeworld,
to place operatives
in the highest
levels of Starfleet,
monitor
your military
installations.
It's a reconnaissance mission,
nothing more.
We should listen to her,
Captain.
They're being driven by fear
just like we are...
unless everything
you said on our date
was just part of an act.
It wasn't.
Enough!
We must not negotiate
with these creatures.
Sit down, Admiral.
Sir?
I said sit down,
or I'll knock you
right on your human butt.
You've been seduced by them,
both of you.
I've had a chance
to see through human eyes,
and I'm beginning to wonder,
are they really so violent?
What if we're wrong?
We can't risk trusting them.
You'd rather risk another war?
Keep talking, son.
Archer's right.
We've got to set aside
our preconceptions
about each other.
Granted, our species didn't meet
under the best
of circumstances,
but maybe we can
make first contact again.
Maybe this time,
we'll get it right.
You believe in
this fellow?
Yes.
There would have to
be a few ground rules.
Name them.
First off, I want to take a look
at that nanoprobe technology.
It scares the hell out of me.
All right...
but I'll need some tactical
information in return--
your genetic alteration
techniques for a start.
I'm sure
something can be arranged.
You on board, Admiral?
Good enough for me.
( majestic theme playing )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 52136.4.
We've managed to avoid
a military conflict
with Species 8472...
at least for now.
In an effort
to strengthen the truce,
we're exchanging technology.
The design schematics
for our nanoprobe
weapons, as requested.
This could go a long way
toward allaying their fears.
Perhaps.
Have a little
faith, Seven.
It's difficult
to have faith in an idea
which may prove
tactically unsound.
Tactically unsound?
Perhaps.
It could also be
the first step toward peace.
It's a risk I'm
willing to take.
Are you sure you
won't join us?
It would be your first
chance to see Earth.
I prefer to remain
aboard Voyager.
If problems arise
while you're in the habitat--
There won't be
any problems--
nothing tactical
at any rate.
We're entering
a stage of diplomacy
where most of the problems
will be cultural.
How do you shake
hands with an 8472?
We'll be fine.
When you ordered me
to disarm the warheads
during the negotiation,
I anticipated
an immediate attack.
I believed they
would take advantage
of your human weakness.
I was wrong.
If I had been
in your position,
we would most likely
be engaged
in a battle with 8472
at this moment.
How did you know?
I didn't.
Like I said...
Faith.
Welcome to Terrasphere 8,
Starfleet Command Re-creation.
I am Admiral Bullock,
and I'll be acquainting you
with our facility.
Questions, comments--
bring them to me.
Problems-- talk
to Lieutenant Kinis.
Commander Tuvok,
you wanted to examine
our thermionic
generators.
Yes.
I'll take you there personally.
Ambassador Nellix.
It's Neelix, sir.
Neelix.
You'll be joining
the Lieutenant.
He'll familiarize you
with our environmental
control technology.
Wonderful. I look
forward to hearing
your perspective
on Vulcans.
You didn't happen
to re-create
a little coffee shop
on Market Street, the Night Owl?
Afraid not.
You're welcome to stay.
Put your feet up.
We won't be returning
to fluidic space
for another day or two.
Thank you, but
the real Earth
is a long way from here.
I'd like to get
back on the road.
What are the chances
they'll listen to you?
I can't promise you
the moon, Captain.
My superiors aren't
as forward-thinking.
Peace with humans?
Wow. They're going
to hit the roof,
but I'll tell them
what happened here today,
and with a pinch of luck,
a few of them
might see the light.
Well, you've got
Voyager's com frequency.
You know how
to contact us.
I hope we can keep
this process alive.
Don't call us,
we'll call you.
( both giggle )
Oh, I almost forgot.
Ah...
( serene theme playing )
Genetically synthesized...
but they smell
just as lovely.
Oh...
( sniffs )
CHAKOTAY:
Looking forward
to going home?
At least I can finally
get out of this form.
No more insomnia.
No more sleeping,
period.
For what it's worth,
you made a terrific human.
Shame...
Hmm?
It's too bad our species
are so different.
Otherwise, I'd ask
you for a second date.
You did offer
to be my guide.
How about a tour
of your realm sometime?
I'd like that.
Well...
I'm due back on Voyager.
We leave at 0400.
I'll never get a chance
to do this again.
( soft theme playing )
Any better this time?
You're a quick study.
( majestic theme swells )
( majestic theme playing )