( birds twittering )
( watery voice ):
Ouch.
Wake up.
Who's there?
Naomi.
Come back later.
You know
what I think?
I think you're scared
of the tree monster.
I'm not scared of any tree
monster, Miss Wildman,
but, as you know,
I need my beauty sleep.
I'm sorry I woke you,
but we have a mission.
You and your missions.
Lucky for you,
your old pal Flotter
has everything ready.
Follow me.
I've laid a trap.
When he climbs this tree,
he'll trip the alarm.
( bells jangling )
Tree monsters are terrified
of high-pitched noises.
I never heard that.
Ah!
It's a well-known fact.
The bell will scare him
high into those branches
where counterweights
will bend the treetop
till it springs back,
catapulting him pondward
and splash.
He'll sink like a log.
But, Flotter...
logs float.
Details, details.
That is a terrible plan.
It's him!
The name's Trevis,
and you are...?
Flotter. Flotter T. Water III.
Well, of course you are, drippy.
You.
Naomi Wildman, but my
friends call me Naomi.
I don't recognize your element.
You're not earth or water
or plasma.
I'm human.
Where do you live?
In space.
Nobody lives in space.
She does...
on a starship
called Voyager.
I'm an explorer.
Really?
An explorer.
Timber.
What's that like?
Well, you know--
space battles with aliens,
strange anomalies.
May I visit your starship?
Well, I'll have
to ask my mom.
You know, for a monster,
you're very polite.
That's because
I'm not a monster.
( bells jangling )
You see that?
I'm not scared one bit.
My bark is worse than my bite.
Maybe we jumped to
conclusions about him.
Well, he may not
be a monster,
but he is stealing
my water with his roots.
Stealing!
Absurd! Why, I ought
to dry you out.
And I ought to chop
you down.
You want a piece of me?
Excuse me. It sounds like
you two need each other.
I mean, think about it.
Flotter, your water
helps his trees grow,
and, Trevis, your branches
shade his pond from the sun.
It's a well-known fact
that the sun
makes water
evaporate.
She's got a point.
The girl's a thinker.
Now, shake hands and make up.
Ugh... moist palms.
Sappy fingers.
Neelix to Holodeck 2.
Naomi here.
It's bedtime.
Can't I stay a little longer?
You know the rules.
Besides, someone special
wants to say good night.
Mom!
Computer, end program.
And how's Flotter?
Grouchy as ever, but we made
a new friend today
named Trevis.
I'll introduce him
to you tomorrow
as soon as you get home.
( transmission static )
I'm afraid the away mission
may take a few more days,
sweetheart.
Days?
Yes...
but I'm bringing you back some
beautiful sillinite crystals
and lots of holopictures
for your data album.
Now be a good girl
and get ready for bed
while I talk to Neelix.
All right.
Sweet dreams.
Samantha?
We ran into an ion storm.
How bad is it?
We took a real beating.
We're trying to make repairs,
but there's
another storm on the way.
( static )
Better go.
Say good night for me?
I've lost the com signal.
A level-7 ionic front is
closing aft at 33,000 kph.
I need more power
to the thrusters
if I'm going to outrun it.
I'll see what I can do.
The leading edge is approaching.
I've given all the power
I can spare, Tom.
It's not enough.
I can't keep ahead
of this thing.
PARIS:
Brace for impact!
TUVOK ( staticky ):
Mayday, mayday.
Delta Flyer to Voyager.
We need assistance.
Warp drive is...
Impulse power is down.
...thrusters only.
...ion storms damaged
our primary systems.
Life support is failing.
We're searching
for an emergency landing site.
We require immediate....
( transmission fades to static)
That was their
last transmission.
We haven't been able
to raise them since.
If they're looking
for a place to land,
they must be in
pretty bad shape.
Anything on
long-range sensors?
We lost their signature
when the second ion storm hit,
but we've triangulated
the coordinates
of the distress call.
They've entered
a planetary system
about .6 light-years
from here.
Problem is, there's
another ion storm--
a level-5--
blocking our path.
Level-5?
We've been through worse.
Let's just batten
down the hatches
and reinforce
the shields.
We're not going to let
a little bad weather
stand in our way.
What about Naomi?
I guess somebody's
going to have
to explain why her
mother's not back.
Maybe we shouldn't
tell her anything.
Why not?
She's a very
sensitive girl.
I-I don't want to alarm
her unnecessarily.
With any luck,
we'll have her mother back
before she starts to worry.
Well, you're closer to her
than anyone.
I'm inclined to let you
take the lead on this.
Thanks, Captain.
All right. Consider
it your mission
to keep her occupied.
Aye, Captain.
Dismissed.
I was thinking...
NEELIX: Oh?
It's time I carried
my weight around here.
Ah. They could use a hand
in the airponics bay.
I was thinking
more of the Bridge.
Captain's Assistant.
Would I get to
fly the ship?
Well, we'd have to take
it up with the Captain.
( door opens )
We need to check
the internal sensors.
( whispering ):
Neelix, don't move.
What's wrong?
The Borg lady.
She has a name, you know.
Seven of Nine, Tertiary Adjunct
of Unimatrix Zero One.
Don't look.
She'll assimilate you.
Naomi, Seven is a nice person
and she's a valuable member
of this crew.
I don't want to be
in her collective.
I don't think
there's much danger of that.
KIM:
Hey, Neelix.
Hey, Naomi.
Neelix,
can I talk with you?
Yeah. I'll be right back.
Sick Bay's running short
on emergency medkits.
We're going to need a few more
if we send another away team
after the shuttle.
I've got half a dozen
stockpiled in Cargo Bay 2.
How is she?
On the Naomi anxiety
scale of one to ten--
where one
is a touch of insomnia,
and ten
is a panic attack--
about five.
SEVEN:
Is this chair occupied?
Yes or no would suffice.
No.
I mean, yes.
Explain.
You can't sit here.
Somebody else is sitting here.
Very well.
So... I thought we'd pay
another visit to Sick Bay.
The Doctor says he has time
to give you a...
botany lesson.
What's wrong?
I am Borg.
No, you're not.
( chuckling )
Could we go to
the holodeck first?
I want to play
another Flotter story.
Well, the Doctor's
expecting you.
I don't like Sick Bay.
Why not?
It's full of creepy things--
alien organs
and hyposprays.
Well, that's not true.
The Doctor talks too much.
Well, that's his way.
Can't you reprogram him
or something?
Oh, I-I don't think
he'd like that very much.
Come on.
Rumor has it there's
a planetoid around here.
WILDMAN:
Sorry, Tom.
The storm
is throwing off my readings.
There's definitely
a big rock nearby.
I just can't find it.
The wave front
is accelerating.
How long till it hits us?
Less than
two minutes.
Great. That gives me 30 seconds
to land this thing.
Samantha, I don't
mean to rush you.
WILDMAN:
Got it.
Class-M atmosphere,
nickel-iron core,
bemonite mantle.
Bemonite? I want to land
this shuttle, not bury it.
73,000 kilometers,
bearing 0 mark 4.
We've entered
the upper atmosphere.
( console beeping )
Nothing but impact craters,
volcanoes...
We can't land here.
The storm is closing.
Increasing shields to maximum.
Just keep us away from the
volcanoes and we'll be okay.
I've got a big meteor crater,
500 kilometers across, 3.7 deep.
I'll take it.
Starboard thrusters
are down.
Tuvok, if you don't have
something positive to say...
We're coming in too fast.
PARIS:
Hang on!
( loud thumps, crashing )
( sighs )
The Flyer has landed.
( exhales )
She needs
immediate medical assistance.
What happened?
We made it.
Delta Flyer's
first landing.
Where...
About three kilometers
beneath the surface.
At least our primary
hull's still in one piece.
Wish I felt the same.
You'll be all right.
Minor concussion,
a few fractures--
nothing I can't handle.
You're a great nurse,
but you're a lousy liar.
You've got
a punctured kidney
and you're bleeding
internally.
You need surgery.
Voyager?
TUVOK:
I've transmitted
another distress call.
No response.
It's all this rock.
I've got to talk to Naomi;
let her know we're okay.
( groans )
Conserve your strength, Ensign.
Mr. Paris and I have
the situation under control.
Nice bedside
manner, Tuvok.
Sam, I'm going to give
you a mild sedative
and something
for the pain.
Any chance we could
abandon the shuttle,
make our way on foot?
Unlikely.
Not only are we buried under
several kilotons of rock,
but the atmosphere
in this cavern
is flooded
with fluorine gas.
Nothing to do
but sit back
and enjoy the view.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've weathered the ion storm
and tracked the Delta Flyer
to an M-class planetoid.
I'm picking up a residual
impulse signature
in the upper
atmosphere.
Try to pinpoint their location.
How's our littlest
crew member?
She misses her mother,
but I don't think
she suspects anything.
I was just about
to take her to the holodeck
for some more
storytelling.
Call me an
optimist, Neelix,
but I'm still counting
on a happy ending.
Me, too.
KIM:
Got it!
The impulse wake leads
to the northern hemisphere:
coordinates 121 mark 16.
Any sign of them?
Plasma fires...
hull fragments...
Either they vaporized on impact
or they're buried
beneath the surface.
Any life signs?
Maybe they beamed out
before the crash.
JANEWAY:
Harry, anything?
Nothing.
We built the Delta Flyer
to take a lot
of punishment.
I'm betting
it held together.
Commander, take rescue teams
down to that crater.
If sensors can't find them,
we'll have to do it
the hard way.
Harry.
DOCTOR:
Now, see the organelle
just over there?
The one that looks like
a little bitty potato?
The mitochondria?
Yes.
"Mitochondria,
The warp core of the cell."
Exactly.
Now, what if I told you
that this fellow
was invited to dinner,
but never got around
to leaving?
What do you mean?
Well, turn back the clock
a few billion years
to when cells
first evolved.
These early cells
had no mitochondria.
They struggled along
without them, making do
with whatever energy
sources they could find.
Then, one day,
a mitochondrial
ancestor arrived,
broke though
the cell wall
and made himself
at home.
They became friends?
The correct term
is "symbiosis."
Friends.
My mom says cooperation is more
important than competition.
Mm-hmm.
She was supposed
to call me today.
Well, she's probably
just a little busy.
Now, let's have a look
at the cell wall.
It looks simple enough,
but believe you me,
there's more here
than meets the eye.
Can we try to call her?
Neelix.
What a pleasure
to see you.
How was school today?
Good.
There's a time for school
and there's a time for...
Flotter.
Uh... aren't you
forgetting something?
Oh.
Thank you, Doctor.
You're quite welcome,
Miss Wildman.
In the blink of an eye,
there was Trevis above us.
Then what happened?
He turned out
to be very nice.
His bark was worse
than his bite.
( chuckles )
Where did you learn
to make such silly puns?
You.
Oh.
Neelix, did you have
a favorite holodeck program
when you were
growing up?
Well, we didn't have
any holodecks on Rinax,
but it didn't matter
because we had
a great big forest
right behind my house.
Really?
Uh-huh.
And my sisters and I would
go exploring every day.
We'd make up
our own stories.
Imagination.
Exactly.
Deck 6, Section 9.
Where are your sisters now?
Oh... they're far
away from here.
I haven't seen them
in a very long time.
How long?
Many years.
But you haven't been on
Voyager for that long.
True, but before that,
my work as a trader
kept me away from home.
That's too bad.
Do your sisters
ever call you
like my mom does when
she's on an away mission?
No.
I bet you miss them.
I do, very much.
Here we are.
Computer, display
chapter headings,
The Adventures  of Flotter.
Let's see.
"Flotter and the Tree Monster"?
Played that one yesterday.
Okay. "Trevis and the
Terribly Twisted Trunk."
I promised I'd save that one
for mom. It's her favorite.
"Flotter, Trevis
and the Ogre of Fire."
Yeah. That one.
Huh. That sounds
a little scary.
It's okay.
I won't be scared
if you're with me.
COMPUTER:
Once upon a time
in the Forest of Forever,
Flotter and Trevis
encountered a strange element
they'd never seen before.
( sustained groaning )
Trevis, you're on fire.
I told him not to touch it,
but this blockhead
never listens.
Stop complaining
and help him.
Me?
Water puts out fire.
Oh, thank you.
Hey, it worked.
Watch this.
Good thinking, Naomi.
Who's the furball?
The name's Neelix.
What caused the fire?
It came from up there.
In a flash.
Lightning.
But the sky is clear.
It doesn't look
like a thunderstorm.
What's your theory, Naomi?
There's only one
other explanation--
the Ogre of Fire.
The Ogre...
...of Fire?
Who's he?
( loud male voice ):
He is me!
And I'm going to burn
this forest to the ground!
Oh! Oh... Oh!
Flotter!
( coughs )
Maybe... we should
play another program.
No, we have to find Flotter.
Hello! Is anyone there?
TREVIS:
Over here.
Trevis, are you all right?
Uh-huh. A little hot
under the bark, maybe.
What about Flotter?
Is he dead?
Neelix?
Well, I...
I don't know.
He can't be dead.
Flotter!
I think it's your bedtime.
But I want to find Flotter.
Don't argue
with your godfather.
Come on, now.
KIM:
Take this to Lieutenant Torres.
You'll find the phaser drills
in Cargo Bay 3.
Aye, sir.
Are you sure you
have time for this?
I know you're busy.
No problem.
Glad to be of service.
Maybe a shade bluer.
And the head's a little
disproportionate,
don't you think?
We're not shooting
for an exact replica, Neelix.
Artistic license.
Sorry.
Guess I shouldn't barge
into your kitchen
and tell you
how to cook.
Flotter-- now there's a name
I haven't heard in a while.
I used to be nuts about those
holostories when I was a kid.
Did you see the one
where Flotter suspects Trevis
to be a rubber tree?
Not yet.
He keeps trying to trip him
to see is if he'll bounce.
Yeah, those two
were a lot of fun.
Actually,
the last scenario
that Naomi chose was
pretty frightening.
No fun at all.
Kids love to be scared.
Not Naomi.
Computer, transfer the design
parameters to the replicator.
How's she holding up?
Fine.
Right now, she's busy
with her homework.
Neelix, what's wrong?
Everything.
Everything's wrong!
Ion storms, crash landings,
alien attacks--
a starship's no place
for a child.
I don't know.
I'd say Naomi's pretty lucky
to be growing up on Voyager.
Lucky?
Think about it.
Think about all the things
she's experienced--
stars being born,
supernovas,
life-forms no one from
the Alpha Quadrant
has seen before.
When I was a kid, I
would have given anything
for a chance like this.
Well, here goes.
Hi, Neelix.
Did you miss me?
You know, I forgot
how ugly this guy was.
Thanks, Ensign.
( imitating Flotter ):
Naomi.
Guess who I found
in the replicator.
Thanks,
but that's not
really Flotter.
Well, Flotter's
not really Flotter.
He's just
a holodeck character.
What are you working on?
I'm researching
the evaporation of water.
Why?
Well, I've been thinking.
Water doesn't just
disappear when it's heated.
It turns into invisible gas.
So, if we could get the
forest to cool down enough,
Flotter might reliquefy.
Clever.
I miss Mom.
I know you do.
When's she coming back?
Soon.
Why hasn't she called?
She must be very busy
cataloguing all the geological
specimens she's collected.
Has anybody talked to her?
( sighs )
Well... not in a day
or two, but...
"Starfleet
Regulation 476-9:
"All away teams must
report to the Bridge
at least once
every 24 hours."
You really are going to make an
excellent Captain's Assistant.
What if something bad
happened to them?
I'm sure everything's fine.
Come on now, bed.
Promise to wake me up
if Mommy calls?
Promise.
Even if it's 0200 hours?
Even if it's 0200 hours.
Sweet dreams.
Neelix?
Computer, access
Personal Database Neelix.
File index 291.
Hello, Alixia.
I'm sorry it's been
so many weeks
since I've thought about you,
but we've been very busy
here on Voyager.
I miss you.
My goddaughter, Naomi,
she's in trouble.
We're in trouble.
She may lose her mother.
Alixia, you always knew
the right thing to do,
the right thing to say.
( sighs )
I wish you were here to help me.
Come on!
Hurry!
We're under attack!
Get up!
( thunderous crashing )
The metreon cascade!
Run!
( gasping )
SEVEN:
Computer, switch to
polythermal imaging
and enhance resolution.
Neelix, do you require
assistance?
No, no, I was
just passing by.
I thought I'd
pay you a visit,
see how things
were going.
How are things going?
I'm mapping the caverns
surrounding the crash site.
How far do they extend?
Approximately
37 kilometers.
What about the search--
anything new?
Every scan reveals
something new,
but as yet,
little of relevance.
Seven...
your family--
your human family--
do you ever
think about them?
Infrequently.
I was only six years old
when I was assimilated.
Not much older
than Naomi is now.
Do you miss your parents?
I barely remember them.
Maybe that's a blessing.
CHAKOTAY:
Rescue team alpha
to Seven of Nine.
Yes, Commander.
We need that data.
I will meet you
at the transporter site.
I adapted.
The child Naomi
will adapt as well.
Borg wisdom.
Lieutenant, get me
an update from beta team.
They haven't checked in
for over an hour.
Coffee, anyone?
Captain?
No, thanks. I've had enough.
One more cup and
I'll jump to warp.
Any news?
I'm afraid not.
No debris,
no life signs?
We've got three teams
beneath the surface
and so far, nothing.
Well, so much for
that happy ending.
We'll turn that planetoid
inside out if we have to,
but I think we have
to be prepared
for the worst.
Maybe it's time
you told Naomi.
No, not yet.
She's an astute girl.
She must be aware that
something's wrong by now.
She's been asking
a lot of tough questions.
"Why hasn't her mother
filed a status report?"
"What if she's in trouble?"
But I've got a big day
planned for her tomorrow.
Plenty of distractions.
She won't have time
to be worried.
Your mission was
to keep her occupied,
not to lie to her.
First thing
in the morning,
I want you to explain
the situation.
I don't think
that's such a good idea.
Why not?
Like I told you,
she's sensitive.
All the more reason
to answer her questions.
With all due respect,
Captain, I'm her godfather.
I know what's best for her.
Neelix...
( door opens )
( door closes )
I realize you
care about Naomi
and you are only
trying to protect her,
but you've got to
tell her the truth.
"Good morning, Naomi.
"Would you like some papalla
juice with your cereal?
"And, oh, by the way,
your mother is buried
under 30 kilotons of rock."
Neelix...
When we know something
for sure...
when we find her mother,
alive or dead...
( stammering ):
I'll tell her then.
Not before.
If you can't
do it, I will.
You don't have the right!
You don't understand
what's at stake here!
When you were her age,
you were safe
and sound on Earth
with two healthy parents
to take care of you.
You never had to worry
about the possibility
of being alone!
You take it from me--
you wouldn't have liked it.
Oh, I know.
You must identify
with Naomi's situation.
When my family was killed,
I lost everything.
I still have nightmares.
It hasn't been easy.
I don't want Naomi
to go through what I did.
I understand,
and you're right,
but this situation
is different.
How so?
Naomi has you.
Neelix, she has to be told,
but I know
she'll be better off
having you here
to help her through it.
First thing
in the morning.
We've got a few hours
until then.
Why don't you come
back on the Bridge?
Give us a hand?
PARIS:
Ready, Tuvok?
Ready.
Cross your fingers.
( sighing )
The magnetic relays
have overloaded.
We better find another way
to polarize this hull
or their sensors
won't be able to pick us up.
We're never getting
out of here.
TUVOK:
Do not give up hope.
The probability
of our being rescued is low,
but not statistically
impossible.
Comforting.
Who's going to
look after Naomi?
You should not concern
yourself with that now.
How can you say that?
My youngest child
has been without
a father for four years,
yet I am certain
of her well-being,
that I conveyed my values
to her before leaving,
and I have confidence
in the integrity
of those around her.
You have been an exemplary
mother to Naomi
and she is in the hands
of people you trust.
She will survive and prosper,
no matter what becomes of us.
Thanks, Tuvok.
Mom!
Neelix?
Computer, locate Neelix.
Neelix is on the Bridge.
Thanks.
TORRES:
Strickler, we need
three more phaser drills.
You two, pattern enhancers
and medkits.
CREWMAN:
Aye, sir.
We're going to have
to recalibrate these tricorders.
Put us with the alpha team.
CREWMAN:
Setting coordinates.
TORRES:
Energize.
Deck 1, Bridge.
( tricorder beeping )
Chakotay to Voyager.
We found what looks like a piece
of the starboard nacelle.
Any sign of the shuttle itself?
Not yet.
SEVEN:
Captain, the cavern has
collapsed ahead of us.
However, I am reading a hull
signature behind the debris.
JANEWAY:
The Flyer?
SEVEN:
I'll need to take
a closer reading.
JANEWAY:
Do it. I want alpha and beta
teams to search for survivors.
Tell Sick Bay to stand
by for heavy casualties.
Naomi?
Naomi...
Computer, locate Naomi Wildman.
Naomi Wildman is
in her quarters.
Clever.
Computer, resume program
"Flotter, Trevis
and the Ogre of Fire."
Program activated.
Commander, I'm reading
duranium alloys.
I believe it is
the shuttle.
Approximately 80 meters
beneath this rubble.
Life signs?
None.
Commander, without
life signs to lock on to,
we cannot beam
the crew out.
Maybe we can transport
the entire ship
to the shuttle bay.
Through 50 kilotons
of bemonite?
Chakotay to Voyager.
Janeway here.
We think we've
found the shuttle,
but we need
to dig it out.
Have all teams rendezvous
at my coordinates.
Acknowledged.
Phaser drills
here and here.
But, hey, B'Elanna,
look on the bright side.
No more day-old pizza
laying around.
And you'll never have
to watch another chapter
of Captain Proton again.
Warning. Life support
has fallen to critical levels.
Don't mind the computer.
She's just jealous
that I'm spending
my last few minutes
talking to you.
So long.
( beeping )
Sam...
it's your turn.
I... haven't thought
what to say yet.
Tuvok, why don't
you go next?
I prefer to make my farewells
in written form.
Computer, begin recording.
Encode message
for delivery to Naomi Wildman.
Acknowledged.
Hi, honey.
I know you're feeling sad
right now,
but I want you to listen
to me very carefully, okay?
First of all, I love you.
Second, I want
you to know
that I'm proud of you,
how smart you are, how funny,
how kind you are
to other people.
And I know that you are going
to grow up
to do extraordinary things.
Last-- and I know
this is a hard one--
try not to be scared.
Warning. Oxygen depletion
in ten minutes.
Listen to Neelix.
He'll be taking care
of you now.
Bye, honey.
Naomi?
Go away!
Where is she?
She doesn't want
to talk to you.
You lied.
I thought
you vaporized.
Naomi reliquefied me.
Now leave.
Computer,
delete characters.
Unable to comply.
Holodeck controls
have been encoded.
Delete us?
I wonder if this liar
can swim?
We could always
hang him from one
of my branches.
Naomi.
Please let me talk to you.
It's okay.
You be nice.
No more lying.
Hey, there.
Is my mother dead?
We don't know.
What happened?
The away team was trying
to avoid an ion storm.
They had to land
on a planet.
I saw that crater.
Something
was burning.
Plasma fires,
pieces of debris...
but not the hull.
Until we know for
sure what's happened,
no one's giving up
on the rescue attempt.
You really think
they might find her?
Yes.
How do I know
you're telling me
the truth this time?
I...
I never told you
this before...
but when I was
much younger,
I lost my mom
in a terrible war...
my father
and my sisters, too.
It was the worst thing
that ever happened to me.
Always wondering...
How did they die?
Were they worried about me?
Could they
still be alive?
I thought if I could just
keep you from wondering...
you wouldn't have to feel
what I did.
You were pretending
that nothing was wrong...
that nothing bad happened.
Do you ever pretend
that nothing bad happened
to your family?
Sometimes.
Does it help?
Not really.
Don't be sad, Neelix.
JANEWAY:
All hands
to emergency stations.
We've got a level-8
ion storm approaching.
Ion storm? What's that?
The Ogre of Fire.
He's attacking us again.
We'd better get back
to your quarters.
FLOTTER:
Naomi.
Don't leave us.
I'll be back.
I promise.
Voyager to Chakotay.
Go ahead.
We've got another
ion storm approaching.
When it hits
the planetoid,
your entire cavern
is going to destabilize.
Just a few more meters
and we'll be close enough
to beam out the shuttle.
How long before
the storm hits?
Six minutes.
Make the most of it,
because it's all you've got.
The storm is moving in.
Shields down to 86 percent.
JANEWAY:
Keep a transporter lock
on the away team.
We'll give them
till the last second.
Helm, lay in a course
out of here.
Stand by to engage
at warp 2.
Aye, sir.
Warning. Oxygen depletion
in two minutes.
I never thought it would
come down to this--
suffocating beneath
kilotons of rock
on some nameless
planetoid.
Did you envision
a more heroic death?
I didn't envision
dying at all.
In accepting
the inevitable,
one finds peace.
If that's another
Vulcan saying, Tuvok,
I'll stick with
"live long and prosper."
( faint drilling sounds )
We're here.
We're here!
Chakotay to Voyager.
Yes, Commander.
Pattern enhancers are in place.
We're ready to transport
the Flyer.
Locking on.
They're in
the shuttle bay.
Helm, engage.
Thank you.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Ensign Wildman has recovered
from her injuries
and the Delta Flyer,
though battered, is intact.
FLOTTER:
And how are you today,
Mr. Trevis?
TREVIS:
Feeling a little stiff,
my slippery friend. And you?
FLOTTER:
Well, now that you mention it,
I'm feeling a little washed out.
( both chuckling )
Well, it's about time
you showed up.
The tea is getting cold.
Samantha?
Is it really you?
Long time no see.
You're all grown up.
I'm an Ensign now.
I missed you.
Likewise.
Well, now that everyone's
reacquainted,
I bet you're all eager
for a new adventure.
Now that you
mention it,
there is a castle that I've
been meaning to explore.
Castle?
I hear a giant beetle
lives there.
Come on, Neelix.
You go ahead.
See you later.
JANEWAY:
Here's to
happy endings.
Captain!
Just checking on my future
Captain's Assistant.
Well, right now, she's off
to conquer a giant beetle.
Oh, sounds like a
dangerous mission.
She can handle it.
She's a courageous girl.
Oh...
Did I ever tell you
about the time
I flooded this
entire forest?
I was six years old.
Flotter claimed we were
in for a dry spell,
so I came up with
the obvious solution.
Why not just divert
the river?
This entire forest was a swamp
by the time we were done.
At which point, Stinger...
NEELIX:
Stinger?
JANEWAY:
The biggest mosquito...
( birds twittering )