( voices yelling and screaming)
( yelling and screaming
get louder )
( yelling and screaming stop)
( sniffs )
COMPUTER:
Regeneration cycle incomplete.
( sniffs )
( snorts in disgust )
( angry yell )
( angry growl )
( sniffs )
( ravenous growling )
KIM:
When I checked
the overnight sensor logs,
this little surprise
was waiting for me.
Maybe I'm not quite awake,
but it looks like its
over 100 kilometers wide.
120. At first, I thought
it was an asteroid cluster
until I picked up
a residual warp signature.
It was
a Borg vessel.
There are tetryon particles
in the debris consistent
with the atmosphere
inside a cube.
Any idea what
destroyed it?
We would need to
run close-range scans
of the hull fragments.
Unless we alter course,
we'll get our chance.
The debris field's
directly ahead.
Then I suggest
we cut a wide berth.
Chances are the
Borg will send
more vessels
to investigate.
Alter course to avoid
the debris. If that's all...
NEELIX:
One other piece of business,
Captain.
It seems we had
another incident
in the Mess Hall
last night.
Return of the
midnight snacker?
NEELIX:
I'm afraid so. Casualties?
A leg of Kelaran
wildebeest I'd prepared
for Ensign Ryson's birthday.
Since Commander Tuvok
has been unable
to round up
any suspects,
I'd like to ask
that stronger
measures be taken.
Perhaps an armed
security detail...
I'd like to ask
permission to replicate
some locking mechanisms
for the cabinet doors.
Granted.
Dismissed.
Naomi Wildman,
Subunit of Ensign
Samantha Wildman,
state your intentions.
I...
Very well.
You leave me no choice
but to report your activities
to the Captain.
Please don't. I was just
observing you.
Explain.
Well, Neelix told
me that the Borg
do a lot of
things they do
because they're
trying to be perfect
and, even though you're not
really a drone anymore,
you still try
to be perfect.
Don't you?
Correct.
Well, if I can learn
to be perfect, too,
then Captain Janeway
will have to make me
her Bridge Assistant.
No such rank exists
aboard this vessel.
Not yet.
And you hope to achieve
this goal by emulating me?
Are you mad?
No. There are
many on this crew
that would benefit
from your example.
So you'll teach me.
Your objective
is admirable.
However, your neocortical
development is incomplete.
You would require several
months of accelerated growth
in a Borg maturation chamber.
Oh... I don't think I
like the sound of that.
Then I suggest that yo...
( cacophony of yelling
and screaming )
( yelling and screaming stop)
Hi.
I'm bored.
Let's do something fun.
Like what?
Swimming?
Oh, I'm not allowed
to go swimming without my mom.
Oh.
Do you like Kadis-Kot?
Love it.
Come on.
( both laughing )
I'll be Bridge Assistant
for a while
then, I'll be
promoted to Ensign.
It'll be Lieutenant after that,
and by the time we reach
the Alpha Quadrant...
Captain Wildman.
Green, grid 14-4.
Kadis-Kot. I win.
( giggling )
You're really
good at this game.
You want a rematch?
Sure.
Captains don't have
much time to play, you know.
That's okay.
I'll be pretty busy by then.
Want to hear the rules
of first contact?
No.
How about the suborders
of the Prime Directive?
I know all 47 of them.
You study too much, Naomi.
Just like
my brother.
I didn't know
you had a brother.
Mm-hmm. 12 of them.
Twelve?
Nine older and
three younger.
We play Kadis-Kot
all the time.
I only have my mom
and Neelix to play with--
when they're not working.
You must get lonely.
A little. You get used to it.
You adapt.
Adapt?
You know, like the Borg.
Borg... I hate Borgs.
You do?
Yeah. They're mean.
Torres to Seven of Nine.
Please report to Engineering.
It's your move.
TORRES:
Seven, respond.
I'm on my way, Lieutenant.
Naomi Wildman...
Yes?
what am I doing here?
We're playing Kadis-Kot.
Seven?
Take a look
at this, will you?
I'm picking up
an energy signal
in the lower
subspace bands
and if I'm not mistaken,
it's got
a Borg modulation.
You're correct.
It is Borg.
I believe it's a neural
interlink frequency.
A what?
A frequency
that integrates
the minds
of Borg drones.
Can you pinpoint
the origin?
I will try.
No offense, Seven,
but you look terrible.
I am not well.
I experienced a brief
lapse in memory
and I am disoriented.
Maybe you should
get to Sick Bay.
No.
This interlink frequency
could explain m...
( voices yelling and screaming)
( yelling and screaming stop)
Do-raq me'roch.
I beg your pardon?
I am the son of K'Vok.
And you?
What house
are you from?
Is this some
kind of a joke?
You wear the uniform
of a Starfleet puh-chah.
What kind of a
warrior are you?
Tom put you up to this,
didn't he?
Well, it didn't work.
Come, warrior,
let me look at you.
Enough, Seven.
( sniffs )
Your blood is sweet!
( yells )
Torres to Security.
Get somebody down here
right now.
You are strong.
You will make
an excellent mate.
Get the hell away from me!
You wish to prove
yourself in battle.
( grunting )
Report.
Seven of Nine attacked
B'Elanna in Engineering.
She's on Deck 9, Section 23.
Force fields.
Don't tell me those two
have actually come to blows.
JANEWAY:
Bridge to Tuvok.
Seven's been contained--
Deck 10, Section 32.
Acknowledged.
We're nearing
her position.
Seven?
Somebody's hurt
and he needs help.
Did I do something bad?
Who are you?
My name's Maryl.
Are you a Vulcan?
Computer, deactivate
force field.
Give me the phaser.
( yelling voices crescendo,
then fade )
You are not a physician,
Commander.
The logical course
of action
would be to take him
to the infirmary.
Maryl?
Subaltern Lorot,
Vulcan High Command.
May I be of assistance?
Yes.
Please accompany
me to Sick Bay.
Certainly.
Clearly he was attacked.
I suggest we use caution.
( yelling voices crescendo,
then fade )
Pahtk!
You will drown
in your own blood.
Keep moving.
( yells )
( gasps )
Seven?
Captain,
why am I here?
You've been unconscious
for nearly two hours.
We believe
you're experiencing
a neurological
disorder.
Voices... I hear voices...
Describe them.
( voices yelling )
They are agitated...
chaotic...
too many voices.
( piercing scream )
( screaming )
Too many voices!
( gasping )
The cortical inhibitor
is destabilizing.
I'm increasing
the neurotransmitter levels.
It's working.
Do you still hear
the voices?
They are fading.
They are gone.
All right.
Let's see what we can do
to keep them
from coming back.
What's the last thing
you remember?
I was in Engineering
assisting Lieutenant Torres.
You have no recollection
of a confrontation
with B'Elanna?
Confrontation?
I'm not sure why,
but you seem to
be manifesting
personalities
other than your own.
Naomi Wildman claims the two
of you played together
for nearly an hour
this afternoon.
You also attacked
Lieutenant Torres.
She told us you called
yourself "son of K'Vok"
and that you initiated
a Klingon mating ritual.
I have no memory
of those events.
DOCTOR:
Come look at this.
Doctor?
DOCTOR:
This is your
neural pattern.
The memory engrams
and synaptic pathways
that define you
as an individual.
Unfortunately,
you're not alone.
13 new neural patterns
have emerged
in your
cerebral cortex--
Klingon, Vulcan,
Terrelian, human
and several others
I can't identify.
How?
They're coming
from within you.
During your time
with the Borg,
the Collective assimilated
hundreds of different species.
All of those neural patterns
were integrated
into the hive mind.
Of course.
That means they're
in your mind, too,
stored within your
cortical implants...
dormant until now.
From what
we can tell,
the various
neural patterns
are surfacing
randomly.
In essence, you've developed
the Borg equivalent
of multiple personality
disorder.
Can you correct
the malfunction?
The cortical inhibitor
is suppressing the effect,
but it's only
a temporary measure.
Lieutenant Torres detected
a Borg interlink frequency.
It could be causing my cortical
implants to malfunction.
The signal appears
to be emanating
from the Borg debris field
we discovered this morning.
Maybe we should jump to warp--
try to get out of range.
The signal permeates subspace.
We cannot avoid it.
Our only hope is
to terminate the signal
at its point of origin.
Set a course for
the debris field.
When we arrive, we
may need your help.
Feel up to it?
Yes, Captain.
Keep a close eye
on her, Doctor,
in case she has any more
unexpected visitors.
Has any drone ever
experienced symptoms
like these before?
The Collective does not
tolerate imperfection.
Any drone with a malfunction
as serious as mine
would be destroyed
immediately.
Lucky for you, this crew
is a little more tolerant.
Oh, there you are.
Lieutenant Torres tells me
you're under the weather.
Correct.
Well, is
there anything
your morale officer
can do to help?
Assignments you
need me to finish
while you recuperate?
No.
I have some wonderful
medicinal teas.
Maybe I could
prepare one for you.
Talaxian homeopathy.
I don't think we're quite
that desperate yet.
How about if I make one of
your favorite nutritional...?
Your concern
has been noted.
The Doctor will inform you
when I am functional again.
Right. Sorry.
Oh, uh...
I almost forgot--
it's from Naomi Wildman.
It's a drawing of Voyager.
Or maybe it's
an asteroid belt.
I'm not sure.
Naomi thought that it
might make you feel better.
Tell her thank you.
DOCTOR:
I suspected as much.
There were several
interruptions
in your
regeneration cycle.
18 minutes,
five minutes, one hour.
I don't recall them.
Let's examine your
neural function logs.
Low serotonin levels
during regeneration.
That's normal.
But look at these spikes
in the prefrontal synapses.
They appear only seconds
before you left the alcove.
You were sleepwalking.
I don't remember entering
this data file.
Looks like we found
the identity
of the midnight snacker.
I'm sure Mr. Neelix
will be relieved.
SEVEN:
Personal Log, Ensign Stone,
Stardate 52188.7.
I just completed my first week
of active duty.
It was a nightmare.
After four years
at the Academy,
I thought
I was ready for anything,
but Captain Blackwood
runs a tight ship
and he seems to take
special pleasure
in tormenting new recruits.
The First Officer tells me
not to take it personally,
but it's hard
to be objective when...
Blackwood.
Captain of the Federation
Starship Tombaugh.
The Borg assimilated
that vessel 13 years ago.
The individual who made
this recording
must have been a member
of the crew.
One of my victims.
Here's another
log entry--
this one encoded
for transmission.
SEVEN ( young voice ):
Hi. Guess who?
I know I promised
to write you every day,
but that's simply not enough.
How about once in the morning
when I resuscitate
and once at night
before I go into torpor
and I'll think about you
nonstop in between.
Wait. I've got a better idea.
Why don't you leave your circle
and visit the colony?
You'd love it here-- sul...
Anything familiar?
I helped to assimilate
thousands of individuals.
I do not remember
each of their names.
Seven, you were a Borg drone
who's now becoming
an individual.
That's practically
unheard of.
There's bound to be rough
spots along the way.
We just have
to get past them.
CHAKOTAY:
Bridge to Seven of Nine.
We're approaching
the debris field.
Acknowledged.
Survivors?
TUVOK:
None.
Any sign of
Borg vessels?
No, sir.
We're the first ones here.
KIM:
I'm picking
up the source
of the interlink frequency,
bearing 027 mark 3.
On screen.
JANEWAY:
Magnify.
SEVEN:
It's a Borg
vinculum.
Vinculum?
The processing device
at the core of
every Borg vessel.
It interconnects the minds
of all the drones.
It purges individual thoughts
and disseminates information
relevant to the Collective.
It brings order
to chaos.
Precisely.
Looks like this one
has established a link
to your cortical implant.
I believe it has
identified me
as an errant drone.
It is attempting to reintegrate
me into the Collective.
The vinculum is
malfunctioning.
It is sending me
erratic commands.
Bringing chaos to order.
Yes.
Can you sever the link?
Not without risking permanent
damage to my own systems.
The vinculum must be
taken off-line.
Permission to beam
it aboard for analysis.
I have worked with this
technology before.
I may be able to disable it.
We're talking about
the heart of a Borg cube.
I'd rather not take it
inside my ship.
Can you disable it remotely?
Yes, but I would need
several days.
The Borg may return by then.
I recommend we take
the vinculum
and leave this
region immediately.
Tuvok, prepare to beam it
to Engineering.
Erect a level-10 force field
and maintain constant
surveillance.
The moment it poses a threat,
send it back into space.
Tom, as soon a it's aboard,
get us out of here, warp 9.
Aye, Captain.
I understand what
you're going through
and I want to help you
in every way I can,
but the safety of this crew
is my first responsibility.
We haven't had the best
of luck with the Borg.
Nor have I.
TORRES:
Let's keep on eye
on those antigrav struts.
Boylan, lock out
all primary command consoles
and reroute transporter controls
to Main Engineering.
Yes, Lieutenant.
( voices yelling and screaming)
Seven?
The voices,
I hear them.
It's your proximity
to the vinculum.
The link is
stronger here.
I'm adjusting your
neurotransmitter levels.
( voices fade )
We better get started.
Don't worry, Lieutenant.
The son of K'Vok
will not be joining us.
Glad to hear it.
Does this qualify
as our second date?
Just think of me
as your chaperon.
So...
where's the off switch?
The vinculum is equipped
with many safeguards.
I will need to access
its transneural matrix
and disable it directly.
( console beeping )
I'm reading
a power surge.
It's a normal response
to my intrusion.
Don't be alarmed.
Curious...
I'm detecting an organism
within the vinculum.
It appears to be
a viral agent.
Let's see it.
It's a synthetic pathogen.
The virus was originally
a biological agent,
but it's mutated.
It's attacking
the vinculum's programs
as it would
living cells.
An organism that
attacks technology?
The cube was infected
three days ago,
shortly after assimilating
an alien shuttlecraft.
Species 6339.
They were the last ones to
come in contact with the cube.
Looks like we've found
our Typhoid Mary.
Species 6339, humanoid.
Warp-capable.
Origin: Grid 124,
Octant 22-Theta.
They first encountered the Borg
approximately
four years ago.
Since that time,
11 billion individuals
have been assimilated.
Three days ago,
the Collective detected
one of their last
surviving shuttlecraft.
A cube was sent
to intercept it.
We believe the virus
was carried
within their bodies.
Once they were
assimilated,
it spread to
the vinculum.
The drones aboard
no doubt
experienced symptoms
similar to my own.
It is no surprise they
destroyed themselves.
I'd like to find
Species 6339.
They may be able
to help us treat you.
Begin long-range
astrometric scans.
See if they have any more
vessels in this region.
Yes, Captain.
I've already begun
a spatial diag...
( voices yelling )
My... My, my.
Look at the size
of that thing.
This viewscreen.
It's got to be one
of the biggest
I've ever seen.
I'll give you
20 bars of latinum for it.
I think the inhibitor's
gone off-line.
Would you come
here, please?
Be quiet. Can't you see
I'm in the middle of a deal?
( sighs )
Name your price, Captain...?
Janeway, and you are...?
DaiMon Torrot.
You're Ferengi.
Of course I'm Ferengi.
Is that some kind of insult
about the size of my ears?
No, not at all.
I'd be happy to
negotiate with you,
but, first, we have
to get you to Sick Bay.
Sick Bay?
What for?
Because... you're ill.
I've never felt better.
Doctor.
I'm afraid you've contracted
a nasty strain
of the Ankaran flu.
We've been treating you
several days. Remember?
No.
Short-term memory loss--
it's one of the symptoms.
Don't worry. It isn't
life-threatening,
but we'll need to treat you...
in Sick Bay.
What is this treatment
going to cost me?
It's free of charge.
Free?
Yes.
You know, I have been
having a nagging pain
in my lower left lobe,
and while you're at it
why don't you run a complete
tricardial diagnostic?
The Ferengi Health Commission
is trying to revoke
my trading license.
Impressive vessel,
Captain. Galaxy-class?
Intrepid.
Ah. Ah! And here we are
in the much talked
about "Sick Bay."
Not exactly state
of the medical art now, is it?
What do you mean?
Low on bio-beds,
terrible lighting,
obsolete instruments.
Lucky for you, I know
a medical supplier
that can spruce this place up
in a nanosecond
and I'll even drop my commission
to a mere... 30 percent?
How generous
of you.
Computer, activate force field.
Force field?
You said I wasn't contagious.
It's for your own safety.
I set the cortical
inhibitor to maximum...
I've been kidnapped!
but it is no longer
suppressing the effect.
These personalities--
are going to
keep surfacing.
All the more reason to shut down
the vinculum as soon as we can.
Even if we do break the
link, it may be too late.
Seven's own neural pattern
is destabilizing.
It could be lost.
SEVEN ( in anguished voice):
Please help me.
I'm looking for my son--
Gregory Bergan,
Lieutenant Bergan.
Have you seen him?
No, I'm afraid not.
From the Starship Melbourne.
Melbourne...
I was supposed to
meet him at Wolf 359,
but Starfleet
sent out a warning
that the Borg were
attacking that sector.
It was too late
for us to turn back.
We were caught
in a terrible battle.
My ship was badly damaged.
We had to leave on escape pods.
I never found out
what happened to Gregory.
Please, I haven't heard from him
in over three days.
Could you check with
Starfleet Headquarters?
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you, Captain.
If... if you do
speak with him,
could you tell him that
his mother is all right
and if he could pos...?
( voices yelling )
Captain...
Seven?
Yes.
The vinculum...
We're preparing
to shut it down right away.
I'll give the order
as soon as Torres is ready.
How long was I... absent?
About 20 minutes.
How many?
Two.
One of whom wanted to acquire
half the items on the ship.
DaiMon Torrot, I believe.
Species 180, Ferengi.
Yes. The other
was a woman
whose son was lost
in a Borg attack.
You'll get through
this, Seven.
I do not share
your optimism.
When you took me
from the Borg
and began to turn me
into an individual,
I found the silence
of my own mind
difficult to bear.
I missed the voices
of the Collective.
But now that I am
an individual
those same voices...
frighten me.
Captain, I don't know
if I can tolerate this
condition much longer.
My courage is
insufficient.
Your job is
to keep trying...
to hold on, even when
you think you can't.
Leave the rest
to me and the crew.
CHAKOTAY:
Meet anyone
interesting?
Just finished swapping jokes
with a Bolian manicurist.
Before that,
I was debating
the finer points of temporal
physics with a Krenim scientist.
12 new personalities
have surfaced
in the past hour alone.
Seven's having
a rough time of it.
The Doctor
had to sedate her.
And how's
the Captain holding up?
I've been better,
Chakotay.
In fact...
I'm starting to wonder
if my first officer
was right all along.
About what?
You always said that
bringing Seven into the fold
might be impossible.
"You can take the Borg
out of
the Collective, but..."
I don't believe that.
Not anymore.
I didn't think she'd last
a day, much less a year.
I'd say you've
proven me wrong.
Torres to Bridge.
We're ready to begin
disabling the vinculum.
Proceed.
Target the transneural matrix.
Stand by to initiate
the dampening field
on my mark.
Three, two, one.
Mark.
Its power output
is dropping.
( monitor beeping )
Doctor to Bridge.
It seems to be working.
Her neural pattern
is stabilizing.
Power output
is down to 77 percent.
71 percent...
Wait a second.
It's increasing.
I am refocusing
the dampening field.
TORRES:
It's still increasing.
TUVOK:
The vinculum is rerouting
its internal circuitry.
It's adapting.
( voices yelling )
Puh-chah me'roq!
( grunts )
DOCTOR:
Engineering!
Mother!
Her synaptic pathways
are destabilizing!
Abort the procedure!
...voices. Help me!
( yelling ):
Abort!
Stand by, Doctor.
Power output at 98 percent.
The force field
is collapsing.
TORRES:
Transfer to emergency power.
It won't work,
Lieutenant.
We must abort.
Tuvok to Bridge.
The procedure was unsuccessful.
The vinculum has returned
to full power.
Acknowledged.
Doctor, report.
Seven's neural pattern
has disappeared, Captain.
It appears that...
the other patterns
have taken over completely.
We've lost her.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Long-range sensors
have detected a vessel
belonging to Species 6339.
We've set a course
to intercept them
in the hopes they can help us
restore Seven of Nine.
I've managed to stabilize
her primary cortical functions,
but the woman in Sick Bay is not
Seven of Nine-- not anymore.
New personalities are emerging
every few seconds now.
She can't finish a sentence
before the next one
rears its head.
It's creating an incredible
strain on her cerebral cortex.
If we don't deactivate
the vinculum soon,
we may never get her back.
Tuvok?
Lieutenant Torres
is taking measures
to prevent the vinculum
from adapting,
but there's no guarantee
she'll succeed.
Captain, I've exhausted every
viable treatment in my database.
Then logic dictates
we go beyond medical science.
I will attempt to mind-meld
with Seven of Nine.
A mind-meld? You consider
that a viable treatment?
Seven's neural pattern--
her sense of self--
is immersed in chaos.
I will attempt
to isolate her true self
and guide it
to the surface.
It's dangerous enough
to meld with one person,
let alone hundreds of
different personalities.
It's too risky.
The risk is
mine to take.
I'm aware of that, but
is this our only option?
I believe it is, Captain.
How long would you
need to prepare?
Captain...
you can't actually be
considering this...
Vulcan mumbo jumbo.
I will require two
hours of meditation.
Begin immediately.
Report to Sick Bay
when you're ready.
You said it yourself.
We've exhausted
every medical treatment.
I just hope I don't find
myself with a second patient.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
On my way.
Commander?
It's them-- Species 6339.
Their vessel
is well-armed, Captain.
I'm picking up
22 phaser cannons
on the aft section alone.
Hail them.
They're responding.
On screen.
I'm Captain Janeway
of the Federation Starship
Voyager.
We recently found a piece
of Borg technology.
It's been infected
with a viral agent
we believe was
transmitted by your...
The vinculum.
You have it?
Yes.
You've made
a terrible mistake, Captain.
A weapon?
Yes. Since the Borg
decimated our world,
we've been looking
for ways to retaliate.
So you created a virus
to infect their technology.
13 of my people were
injected with the virus.
They allowed themselves
to be assimilated
so that the virus would spread
to this vinculum.
Once another Borg ship
had retrieved it,
they would be infected as well.
Then another cube,
and another...
We had the opportunity
to infect dozens, even
hundreds of Borg vessels
until you interfered!
Why?
Your virus has had one
unexpected casualty...
a member of my crew.
It wasn't designed
to infect other species.
She's Borg.
CHAKOTAY:
We liberated her
from the Collective
over a year ago.
She's an individual now.
We were hoping you could
help us treat her.
We designed that virus
to destroy Borg, Captain.
We never considered a treatment.
I'm afraid your
drone won't survive,
but we must return the vinculum
to the debris field immediately.
If the Borg arrive first,
we'll have lost our chance.
And those 13 people
will have died in vain.
All right.
We'll return it to you,
but first we need to try
to save our crew member.
We think we have a way
to counteract
the vinculum's effects.
B'Elanna?
I'm going to try
to remodulate
our dampening field
to compensate...
We don't have
time for this.
The vinculum, Captain.
I can't give it to you.
Not yet.
You've scanned our vessel.
You're aware of our firepower.
You could undoubtedly do
significant damage to Voyager
and to the vinculum.
Is that what you want?
The vinculum survived
the destruction of one ship.
What makes you so sure
it won't survive another?
Doctor...
Seven.
A necessary precaution.
A few of your... guests
have been violent.
The vinculum.
It keeps adapting.
We haven't been able
to shut it down.
Your own neural pattern was
nearly destroyed in the process.
I wasn't sure
I'd find you again.
I am damaged.
One of your... personas
didn't appreciate
the restraints.
She seemed intent on forcing
her way to freedom.
I apologize.
It was hardly your fault.
You're ill.
Irrelevant.
I am Borg--
I should be able to adapt.
Surprise--
you aren't invincible.
I suppose that's something
we'll have to tackle
in our next social lesson.
( voices yelling and screaming)
Voices?
They're getting louder.
It won't be long
before I lose you again.
( voices fade away )
It's my duty as
your physician
to inform you of an
alternative treatment.
What treatment?
Commander Tuvok has
proposed a mind-meld
to help stabilize
your neural pattern.
I had a
similar reaction.
If you don't approve...
What is the probability
of success?
I don't know.
A mind-meld is hardly
a standard medical practice.
Are there any risks to Tuvok?
He could suffer
brain damage,
but he's confident he'll
be able to break the meld
before that happens.
Even if we do
shut down the vinculum,
it may not be enough.
If Tuvok can do
anything to help me...
I understand.
Doctor...
you have shown
a great deal of patience.
Not at all.
Inform the crew that I am
also grateful for their efforts.
You'll be able
to tell them yourself afterward.
( voices yelling
and screaming )
Seven!
Voices!
Concentrate.
( groaning )
Focus on the
sound of my voice.
Get them out, please!
I can't...
No! No!
( voices fade away )
Report.
The alien vessel
is coming about.
They're charging weapons.
Shields.
As if the meld weren't
dangerous enough,
the aliens are trying
to take the vinculum by force.
Commander Chakotay
is at tactical.
The Captain wants
you here with Seven.
This will allow me
to monitor your
neural activity
for the duration
of the meld.
At the first
sign of trouble...
You will do nothing.
I beg your pardon?
There will undoubtedly be
many signs of trouble.
You must have faith
in my ability to endure them.
I'll try. I just
hope my faith
doesn't leave the two
of you brain-damaged.
Your concerns
have been noted, Doctor.
With all of these new
personalities floating around,
it's a shame
we can't find one for you.
Computer,
deactivate
force field.
( faint screaming voices )
Why am I tied
to this bed?
Please let me go.
pahtk!
I'll rip out your
throat, coward!
( yelling )
Name your price.
Ten bars of latinum?
Twenty?
This isn't medicine.
It's torture!
I'll sue for malpractice!
I fail to see the logic
in this meld, Commander.
My mind to your mind.
You are but one mind
confronting thousands.
My thoughts
to your thoughts.
You will not succeed.
TUVOK: Your mind to my mind.
SEVEN: Let me go.
My mind to your mind.
We've got to evacuate.
My thoughts to your thoughts.
Listen to me!!
My mind to your mind.
They're trying to assimilate
the ship! Let me go!
My thoughts
to your thoughts.
Where's my
mommy? Mommy!
My mind to your mind.
Mommy...
My thoughts to your thoughts.
( voices yelling and screaming)
Seven?
Seven!
( all yelling and screaming )
( yelling deafeningly )
Seven!
( male screaming )
( groaning )
( sobbing ):
I'm lost! Somebody help me!
Please! I don't like it here!
I want to go home!
I can't find my...
Mommy! Please! Help me!
Please! I don't
want to stay here!
I want to go home!
I don't like it!
Please help me!
I want to go home!
These people are scary!
Please don't go!
Please! Why are you
leaving me here?!
Don't go!
Please! I don't
like it here!
( bloodcurdling scream )
( gasping )
Sick Bay to Engineering.
How long until the vinculum's
off-line?
Two, maybe three minutes...
provided Voyager can stay
in one piece for that long.
Shields down to 60 percent.
Evasive maneuvers.
Target their
weapons array.
Targeting systems
are malfunctioning.
We're losing power
to main thrusters.
Shields to 35 percent.
Reroute all available
power to shields.
Chakotay, initiate
manual targeting.
Torres to Bridge.
The vinculum's stopped adapting.
I think the new dampening field
is working.
We should have it disabled
in the next 60 seconds.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Neurochemical synapses
are destabilizing.
Computer, increase power
to the cortical inhibitors.
Unable to comply. Power
transport systems are off-line.
Tuvok, if you can hear me,
we have to terminate the meld.
Tuvok! Tuvok!
Le'rah tuh me'roq.
( voices yelling and screaming)
SEVEN:
Commander?
Seven!
( screaming continues )
Power output's down
to 29 percent.
22... 17...
( alarm beeping )
Bridge, we just lost
the field emitters.
We took a direct hit
to the power grid.
Stand by. We're switching
to emergency backup.
Seven!
Bridge, the vinculum's
powering up again.
JANEWAY:
The field emitters
are back on line.
Pull the plug.
It's working.
Power output down to 19 percent.
13 percent.
( voices yelling and screaming)
Seven!
Tuvok!
( vinculum powering down )
TORRES:
It's done, Captain.
The vinculum's off-line.
( yelling voices echo
and disappear )
( Seven panting )
Seven?
( weakly ):
Yes.
DOCTOR:
We have her back, Captain.
Hail the lead vessel.
Tell them we're surrendering
the vinculum.
No response.
Lock onto the damn thing.
Beam it into space.
CHAKOTAY:
Transport complete.
They're withdrawing.
Take us out of here, Tom.
Warp 9.
Yes, ma'am.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 52356.2.
After nearly a week
of regeneration,
Seven of Nine has finally
recovered from her ordeal.
DOCTOR:
Neuroprocessor, cortical
receptors, all stable.
She's fit
to return to duty.
What about her other
personalities?
Any sign of them?
Those neural patterns
have returned to
their dormant state.
The voices will not return?
I suppose that depends
on your perspective.
You may not hear them,
but I suspect they'll
always be with you.
The members of this crew put
themselves at risk to help me.
I am unsure how to reciprocate.
Let's start with
something small.
Like a recalibration
of the EPS manifolds?
B'Elanna's expecting
you in Engineering.
I will join her shortly.
There is a crew member
I must see first.
These are star charts for
the next three systems
Voyager will pass through.
Familiarize yourself with them.
Understood.
Sociological data
regarding 173 Delta
Quadrant species.
Study it.
I will.
As Bridge Assistant,
you will find this
information relevant.
Consider it
"assimilated."
There is one more
assignment.
I require
your assistance.
Me?
I wish to participate
in recreational activities.
Great.
Kadis-Kot.
Instruct me how to play.
I will comply.