DOCTOR:
...and since I was
the only crew member
who could survive
the corrosive atmosphere,
it was up to me to
retrieve the data module
and save the day.
Ah, here I am...
mission accomplished.
Ah...
DOCTOR:
Then, of course
there was
the perilous mission
to La'voti V.
You remember that one,
don't you, Mr. Paris?
How could I forget?
Here you are
after your unfortunate slip
into the fetid mud pits
of Pala Mar.
( chuckling )
Hey, I was pushed.
Of course you were.
JANEWAY:
Thank you,
Doctor.
We've all enjoyed
your holo-images enormously.
DOCTOR:
Oh, but I haven't
finished yet.
There's more?
The best is yet to come,
Lieutenant.
I've created a fascinating
12-part holographic essay
which I call "Under the Skin:
Humanoid Anatomy as Art."
Let's begin
with this stunning magnification
of the Vulcan
reproductive gland.
2100 hours, Commander.
All systems
reporting normal.
CHAKOTAY:
Acknowledged.
Like I said, it's 2100 hours.
I heard you the first time,
Harry.
They've been in
there over an hour.
I'm aware of that.
Didn't the Captain ask you
to rescue them after 30 minutes?
Harry, you and I
were lucky enough
to enjoy the Doctor's
scintillating exhibition
for two full hours.
Would it really be fair of us
to deny our friends
the same
unforgettable experience?
Of course not, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you for coming.
We'll do it again soon.
We've still got thousands
of light-years to while away.
This could be a weekly event.
What happened to going
to Yellow Alert
after half an hour?
Commander Chakotay appears to
have disobeyed a direct order.
Definitely grounds
for court-martial.
( Torres chuckles )
Hey, Neelix.
Coffee?
I could use
a whole pot.
Let me guess.
The Doctor's
photographic essay?
One mind-numbing
image after the next.
Oh, I don't know.
I thought some of those
pictures were pretty funny.
You mean like the one where Tom
slipped into a mud pit?
( laughing )
You're famous.
Then, of course,
there's the one
depicting a certain
Chief Engineer
with her foot stuck
in a plasma injector.
What?
Really? Well, I seem
to have missed that one.
The Doctor must have taken it
out of the exhibition.
Oh, I can't wait to
get my hands on it.
Maybe I can distribute it to
everyone's personal database.
Try it
and I'll kill you...
right after I finish deleting
the Doctor's program.
What'd you put in
this coffee, Neelix?
KIM:
I'm reading
a massive energy wave
900,000 kilometers
off the starboard bow,
heading right for us.
Source?
Unknown.
Shields up.
Evasive maneuvers.
The wave just changed course.
It seems to be tracking us!
Go to warp 8.
Too late.
Engines are down.
Everybody hang on.
All stop.
Shields are holding.
Minor damage
to the hull plating
on Deck 15.
No injuries.
Stand down Red Alert.
KIM:
Captain, when
the wave hit,
our communications array
received a download.
What sort of download?
I'm not sure.
Lots of information.
I can't decipher it,
but there's an audio component.
JANEWAY:
Let's hear it.
( screeching, whistling
alien language )
Harry, try all the standard
decryption algorithms.
JANEWAY:
It's strange.
The wave
followed us,
but it didn't cause any damage.
Instead, we get a download
to our database.
I'd say it's a pretty good bet
somebody's trying
to tell us something.
PARIS:
The wave left
a residual ion trail.
We might be able
to locate its point of origin.
Set a course.
Looks like it's taken
quite a beating.
Life signs?
One. Nonhumanoid.
It's very faint.
Probably injured.
Beam it to Sick Bay.
Are you sure that's
wise, Captain?
I'm betting that
message we received
was some sort
of distress call
and if we're
going to help,
I'd rather do
it on Voyager.
The physiology is so unusual
the tricorder can't make heads
or tails of it.
The creature's
obviously injured,
but I haven't a clue
how to treat it
or even diagnose it.
My scans came up with something
interesting, Captain.
The interfaces on
the alien's vessel
can only be activated
chemically.
I'm guessing that this life-form
somehow interfaces directly
with the ship's systems
using biochemical secretions
to give commands.
That would explain
how it can fly a ship.
I'm hoping this can
also help us figure out...
( alien screeches )
( Torres grunting,
alien screeching )
( yelling )
No! You'll hurt B'Elanna!
Get it off of me!
Janeway to Kim.
Beam the alien life-form
back to its vessel now!
I'm having trouble
getting a lock.
( gasping )
It's piercing
her neck!
Her heart and lungs
are seriously compromised
and her kidneys are failing.
The creature's also secreting
some kind of paralyzing agent
into her bloodstream.
How do we get
it off her?
I can't remove it surgically,
not without doing
irreparable harm
to B'Elanna's internal organs.
Can we get a lock
on the creature--
transport it off?
Not unless we want to beam
B'Elanna's cardiopulmonary
system along with it.
PARIS:
We have to do something!
No one is disputing
that, Mr. Paris.
The question is, what?
If I'm to have any hope
of devising a treatment,
I'll need to brush up
on my exobiology.
What do you mean,
"brush up"?
Don't you have all this
information in your database?
I may be a walking
medical encyclopedia,
but even I don't
know everything.
My matrix simply isn't
large enough.
Maybe we can do
better than giving you
a crash course
in exobiology.
Maybe we can provide
you with a consultant.
I'd be delighted, but how?
By isolating the computer's
exobiology data files
and merging them
into an interactive matrix.
A hologram.
Exactly.
That may not be
as simple as it sounds.
It would need to be nearly
as sophisticated as I am--
tactile interfaces,
personality subroutines...
Harry could do it.
Search the database
for a leading exobiologist.
If you want to add
a personality,
it may as well be based
on a real person.
I'll have Harry meet you
on Holodeck 2.
Stay with her
and monitor her vital signs.
Call me if there's any change.
KIM:
I still have my doubts
about this, Doc.
It's one thing to
create a simple hologram,
but you're trying to merge
an extensive database
with an interactive matrix.
Don't be a pessimist,
Mr. Kim.
Together, we'll create
a masterpiece
of holographic art.
A subject for your
next slide show?
Perhaps.
Can't wait.
What's the name of that
exobiologist you chose?
Crell Moset.
Here's the file.
Let's start with
the parameters
for physical
appearance.
Computer, display
a holographic simulation
of Crell Moset.
Have you mentioned
to anyone else
that this guy's
a Cardassian?
What difference
does it make?
Maybe you haven't heard.
They're not the exactly
the friendliest folks
in the galaxy.
I don't care if he's
the nastiest man
who ever lived, as long as he
can help us save B'Elanna.
Good point.
Computer, transfer
all referenced medical files
to the simulation.
Transfer complete.
Now install
personality subroutines
and voice approximation.
Installation complete.
Dr. Moset, I'd like
to consult with you
about an alien life-form.
( squeaky, distorted voice):
I am Crell Moset,
Chief Exobiology Specialist
Cardassia Prime,
( staticky ):
...to perform
all surgical procedures.
This is going well.
What's wrong?
Some sort of overload
in the interactive matrix.
Can you clear it up?
I'm trying.
Computer, install
a recursive algorithm.
Algorithm installed.
Try it again.
Dr. Moset?
( normal voice ):
My friends call me Crell.
It's a pleasure
to meet you, Crell.
And you, good man,
what's your name?
Actually, I'm in between
names at the moment.
I'm an Emergency
Medical Hologram.
Interesting.
But his friends
call him Doc.
Aha. May I presume?
Certainly.
So, Doc, how can an
old surgeon like me
help a technological
marvel such as yourself?
Oh, well...
I've got a patient
with a rather unusual problem.
She's become fused
with a nonhumanoid life-form
I know nothing about.
Nonhumanoid exobiology
happens to be one
of my specialties.
That's exactly why we've
created your program.
Program?
You're a hologram as well.
Interesting.
I'd like to see the
patient right away.
Mr. Kim, would you do
the honors, please?
No problem.
Listen,
if he destabilizes again,
take him off-line
and call me.
Understood.
Lieutenant,
may I present
Crell Moset?
It's a pleasure.
She's been drifting
in and out of consciousness.
Don't be rude, Lieutenant.
To him?
No offense, Doc,
but he's just a...
A brilliant scientist
who's here to help us.
This way, Crell.
Hmm... I can see why
you're having difficulty.
Its physiology
doesn't match
any of the standard
templates in our database.
My guess would be
a cytoplasmic life-form.
I agree. And from
what I can tell,
it has co-opted
her vital systems.
She's Klingon...
No, the cranial ridges
are less pronounced.
Klingon-human hybrid.
Exactly.
Let's hope your instincts
about the creature
are equally insightful.
I'm afraid
this one is going
to require more
than a visual assessment.
You have an
isomolecular scanner.
No. Just a standard issue
Starfleet tricorder.
No wonder you're having problems
making an accurate diagnosis.
I suggested an upgrade
to the Starfleet people
at a joint medical conference,
but they assumed I was
just an arrogant Cardassian
trying to prove
his superiority...
or maybe they thought
I was a spy.
I hope you weren't
too offended.
It's an unfortunate reality.
Sometimes even enlightened
races can't find common ground.
I may be able
to recalibrate this thing.
There. That should help.
Amazing.
Well, someone from Starfleet
appreciates me.
I've instructed the computer
to assign symbols
to all the tones received
in the transmission.
Looks like there were over
10,000 separate sounds
used in this section
of the message.
It's going to be
a tough code to crack.
Maybe we can get
a little help
from the alien
vessel's data banks.
Good idea.
Janeway to Seven of Nine.
Yes.
Any chance of downloading
the alien's data banks?
We're looking for anything
that might help us
understand their language.
We don't know how much time
B'Elanna has left.
We must move quickly.
The vessel is on the verge
of a complete systems failure.
Prepare to
download the data.
I heard the Captain.
Is there a problem?
No. No problem.
You seem uncomfortable
taking orders from me.
It's just that I'm
used to taking orders
from B'Elanna,
that's all,
and to tell you the
truth, she doesn't...
Doesn't like me.
Yes, I am aware of that.
However, the Captain
left me in charge
during Lieutenant Torres'
absence.
Her feelings about me
are irrelevant.
Activate the interface
transceiver.
Begin the download.
I'm picking up
a fluctuation
in the alien ship's
power source.
It's disrupting
the interface transceiver.
Reinitialize.
I'm working on it.
Its systems are overloading.
Red Alert.
Engineering to Bridge.
The alien vessel
is destabilizing.
Its destruction is imminent.
Can you download
the information first?
We're trying.
Captain, it's going to explode.
Ensign, back us off.
What do we know so far?
The life-form has taken
control of her body
at the autonomic level,
drawing proteins
from her tissues,
white blood cells
from her arteries.
Which can be interpreted
in several ways.
A form of attack.
I find it odd
that a species would evolve
an attack mechanism
that would leave it
so vulnerable.
Why not do its damage
and retreat?
A parasite perhaps?
Yes, I think so,
but not any ordinary variety.
It's unlikely it could
sustain itself like this
over the long term.
Its own systems
are damaged.
It's doing this
as a stopgap measure
to keep itself alive.
So the patient's heart,
lungs, kidneys--
they're all augmenting
the alien's damaged system.
It's using B'Elanna
as a life preserver.
But if it needs
her to survive,
it's not about to let
go without a fight.
I'd like to think
that's a fight
you and I can win.
We do work well
together.
I just wish we had
access to my laboratory.
It has all the instrumentation
we would need.
Well, we'll just
have to improvise.
Not necessarily.
We may be able to create
a reasonable facsimile
of your laboratory
in our holodeck--
providing, of course,
you can give an
accurate description.
Tom.
Hey, there.
I can't move.
I know.
But don't worry.
We'll get this thing off you.
Just think.
I could force
you to listen
to rock 'n' roll all day
and you wouldn't be able
to do a thing about it.
Who is that?
Relax.
He's just a hologram--
a specialist in exobiology.
The Doc thinks
he might be able
to help you.
Can't he find somebody else?
Apparently, this guy's the best.
Besides, he's just
a walking database.
Hologram or not,
he's Cardassian.
As far as I'm concerned,
they're all
cold-blooded killers.
I understand how you feel.
Unfortunately,
that cold-blooded killer
may be the only one
who can save your life.
Impressive.
Mm.
Is this where you did your work
on the Fostossa virus?
No. Actually, I was
on Bajor at the time,
during the occupation.
A sad chapter in
Cardassian history.
We had no business
being there,
but try telling that
to the politicians.
When I think of the resources
that were squandered,
the lives that were lost...
From what I understand,
you saved thousands of lives.
In retrospect,
I don't know how.
The military had
everything they needed,
but the civilian hospitals?
No staff,
the crudest equipment...
Don't tell me.
You were forced
to improvise.
Yes!
I know what that's like.
I didn't have
the resources
to try traditional methods,
so I experimented
with procedures that never
would have occurred to me
under ordinary circumstances.
The discovery of the cure was
almost accidental, really.
You're being
modest, Crell.
No.
You made
medical history.
You won the Legate's
Crest of Valor.
Awards aren't
important, Doc.
It's the work
that matters.
Of course.
Still, the recognition
of your peers, your government,
must be very satisfying.
I'm sure you've made your
share of breakthroughs.
Naturally. Unfortunately,
no one from Starfleet
ever hears about them.
I toil in obscurity.
Why don't you show me
your patient records?
At least I'll know about
your accomplishments.
All right.
Everything seems
to be in order.
Shall we get to work?
Computer, create
a holographic re-creation
of the alien in Sick Bay.
Hand me that cortical
stimulator, will you?
Yes. Thank you.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
While the Doctor seems
to be making progress,
Commander Chakotay and I
have hit a wall
in our attempt
to decipher the alien message.
It was a distress call, right?
So maybe if we retransmitted
that message,
others of the species would
realize we need their help.
We don't know
where they are.
We'll send it on
all subspace bands.
If they're out there,
they'll hear it.
They might turn out
to be unfriendly.
The Doctor's pretty sure
the alien is simply
trying to survive. I agree.
It'll be a difficult
first contact,
but we might find a way
to communicate.
It's worth a shot.
Tuvok, reroute auxiliary power
to the deflector dish.
Retransmit the alien's message
on all subspace bands.
TUVOK:
Aye, Captain.
Deflector at full capacity.
Chakotay.
( humming melody )
( humming same melody )
( humming together )
I'm sorry.
My wife tells me
I'm tone deaf.
Not at all.
You were right on key.
If you enjoy music,
we can run some opera programs
after we're finished.
I'd like that.
I think we're ready
for a look inside.
Scalpel?
Forgive me for saying so,
but this appears to be
a rather crude instrument,
especially when we have
such advanced equipment
at our disposal.
I often find
the simplest tool
is the most effective.
All of our
elaborate scanners
and laser scalpels--
they remove us
from our subjects.
Actually feeling
the anatomy,
the consistency of
the internal organs,
it can be very
instructive.
Why don't you
do the honors?
Make a vertical incision, say,
12 centimeters, starting here.
( squealing )
We're hurting it.
Doctor, it's a hologram.
Of course.
I guess as a hologram myself,
I have a certain empathy.
Keep going.
Extraordinary.
Look at that
series of nodes.
They appear
to be clustered
along the
primary nerve.
Multiple neocortices,
I'd say.
Suggesting a highly
intelligent species.
Yes, but also presenting
us with a point of attack.
Attack?
If we induce
a neurostatic shock
in one of these nodes,
I believe it will
travel to the others,
the creature will
lose motor function
and we'll be able
to remove it.
The procedure will probably
kill the creature.
Probably.
I'd like to find a way
to save them both.
So would I
in an ideal situation,
but we have to set
priorities,
which, in this case,
is your crewmate.
This is a sentient
life-form.
For all we know,
it could be this
species' Einstein,
its Picasso.
Or he could be
a psychotic criminal.
The point is,
we don't know
and we have
choices to make.
Your program's
destabilizing.
This is such poor timing.
I'll have to take
you off-line,
but don't worry.
We'll have you up and
running again in no time.
Computer, take Medical
Consultant Program off-line.
Doctor to Ensign Kim.
Go ahead, Doc.
Our new program's
destabilizing.
I'll meet you in Sick Bay.
We'll try
to reinitialize him there.
Tabor, I could use some help.
Yes, sir.
KIM:
Try again.
No luck.
Would it be easier
if we reduced
the hologram's memory load?
Maybe, but I don't want
to do that unless
we absolutely have to.
What's going on?
My consultant's gone off-line.
The Cardassian?
You can leave him off.
I'm surprised
by your attitude, Lieutenant.
I never took you for someone
who would make generalizations
based on race.
When it comes to Cardassians,
I'm guilty as charged.
I understand your experience
with them was unpleasant,
but if you give Crell a chance,
I think you'll find
that he's a friendly,
compassionate man,
not to mention a genius
who's trying to save your life.
I'll skip the introductions
if it's all the same to you.
Suit yourself,
but you should know
I plan on asking the Captain
to keep him on
as a permanent consultant.
I'm not the only one who's going
to have a problem with that.
How's it coming?
We're close.
Actually, I think
that should do it.
Good.
Computer, reactivate
Medical Consultant Program
Beta-1.
Hello, again.
My God.
What's wrong?
That's Crell Moset.
Yes. Do I know you?
He killed my brother,
my grandfather--
hundreds of people.
He's a mass murderer.
You must be mistaken.
It's no mistake.
Moset performed experiments
on living people.
Thousands of Bajorans
were killed
in his so-called hospital.
Is this true?
No, no. He's...
There must be some
misunderstanding.
The liar.
Take it easy, Tabor.
Whoa. He's just
a hologram.
I'm upsetting him.
I should go.
I'm sorry about this.
( sighs )
Computer, transfer
Medical Consultant Program
to Holodeck 2.
TABOR:
I can still remember
the sounds
his instruments made...
the screams of his patients...
the smell...
of chemicals and dead flesh.
He operated on
my grandfather...
exposed his
internal organs
to nadion radiation.
It took six days
for him to die.
He blinded people so he
could study how they adapted,
exposed them to polytrinic
acid just to see
how long it would take
for their skin to heal.
Ensign, the man you're accusing
cured the Fostossa virus.
He stopped an epidemic that
killed thousands of Bajorans.
By infecting hundreds
of people...
so that he could experiment
with different treatments--
old, helpless people...
like my grandfather...
because he considered
their lives worthless.
How do you know this?
Everybody knew.
I remember some of the Maquis
under my command
talking about an infamous
Cardassian doctor.
Could these simply
have been rumors
spread by Bajorans
who hated the Cardassians?
I was there.
I don't understand
why this isn't
in our database.
The Cardassians
didn't exactly publicize
their wartime medical practices.
I wouldn't be surprised
if the real Moset went on
to live a normal life.
He's the Chairman
of Exobiology
at the University of Culat.
We may not be able
to do anything
about the real
Moset, Commander...
but the program
should be destroyed.
Every trace of
that man's research
should be deleted
from the database.
I had a bad feeling
about that hologram
the second I saw him.
Looks like your instinct
was right.
I won't let him near me.
You're kidding, right?
No, I am dead serious.
B'Elanna...
If I let that pig
operate on me...
I'll be benefiting
from other people's suffering.
You're not being rational.
I won't do it.
( alarm bleeping )
What's happening?
Her cytotoxin levels are
going through the roof.
Pulse is rapid
and irregular.
No doubt you've said
something to upset her.
What she's upset about, Doc,
is your Cardassian buddy.
Tell him.
DOCTOR:
Tell me what?
She refuses
to let him treat her.
B'Elanna, we're very close
to a solution.
Do it...
( panting):
...without him.
I don't know that I can.
Find another way.
( gasps )
She's going
into cytotoxic shock!
Two milligrams inaprovaline!
DOCTOR:
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
I've managed to stabilize
Lieutenant Torres
for the time being, but
the matter of how to proceed
with her treatment
remains unresolved.
Isolate data block 0459.
DOCTOR:
Ensign.
You wanted to see me?
We've been looking
for evidence
that might support
Tabor's accusations.
Anything?
Actually, that's
why we called you here.
It's not looking good.
Show me.
We've been reviewing data
on the Cardassian
occupation of Bajor--
the alleged site
of Moset's crimes.
Strategic information,
log entries kept in battle,
sensor scans from Starfleet
vessels-- this, for example.
Requisition records from
one of Crell Moset's hospitals.
He was purchasing
biochemical agents,
including every known strain
of the Fostossa virus.
Of course he needed
samples of the virus.
That's how vaccines
are developed.
Take a look at
the requisition orders.
DOCTOR:
Moset didn't ask for
any of the enzymes
normally required for
synthesizing a vaccine.
It gets worse.
Four days after he received
the virus samples,
there was a minor outbreak
of Fostossa
in the vicinity
of his hospital.
Prior to that date,
there had not been a single case
in the entire province.
I have to report
these findings
to Commander Chakotay.
It is curious.
The Borg are accused of
assimilating information
with no regard for life.
This Cardassian
did the same
and yet, his behavior
is tolerated.
Ah, there you are.
I'm almost ready
to begin the surgery.
Lieutenant Torres won't allow
you to have anything to do
with her treatment.
Because of that Bajoran?
We've gathered some
corroborating evidence.
It appears that he's
telling the truth.
You committed
a series of atrocities
during the Cardassian War.
Thousands of Bajorans
died on your surgical tables.
That's absurd.
And even if it were true,
I'm only a hologram
and I have no memory
of those events.
They're not part
of my programming.
But you are the holographic
representation of Crell Moset.
Your program,
despite all its brilliance,
is based on his work.
He infected patients,
exposed them to polytrinic acid,
mutilated their living bodies
and now we're reaping the
benefits of those experiments.
Medically, ethically,
it's wrong.
What do you suggest
we do about it?
I'm not sure.
We may have
to delete your program.
Delete me?
What about our patient?
I suppose I'd have to try
and treat her on my own.
No offense,
but you need me.
I realize that.
You're a physician.
You know there's always
a price to pay
for the advancement
of medical science.
Sometimes that price
is too high.
Torture?
Your word, not mine.
I cured the Fostossa virus,
didn't I?
So these experiments
you say I conducted
obviously helped me
devise a treatment.
Imagine how many lives
would have been lost
if I hadn't eliminated
this disease.
That doesn't justify
using people
in laboratory experiments.
As I explained to you,
during the occupation,
I was forced to improvise.
I used what resources I had.
And ethical considerations,
they mean nothing to you?
Ethics are arbitrary.
How do you suppose your own
database was developed? Hmm?
My God, half the medical
knowledge acquired on Earth
came through experiments
on lower animals.
But not people.
It's convenient
to draw a line
between higher and lower
species, isn't it?
This is the 24th century, Crell.
Your kind of barbarism
ended a long time ago
or, at least, it should have.
What difference
does it make
how long ago the
research occurred?
What matters is
that we can use it
to help patients today.
Now, are you going
to delete my program and all
of the research it contains,
or are we going to use it
to save B'Elanna's life?
( door chimes )
Come in.
Commander.
This request of yours
to be relieved of duty--
I won't grant it.
I have the right
to resign my commission.
For what reason?
Moral objections
to this ship's medical policy.
( sighs )
I understand how
difficult this is for you,
but you've got to
let go of the past.
Focus on today,
and today,
B'Elanna's life
is in danger.
Everything else
should be put aside.
You don't have the right
to violate the memory
of my family.
As long as that Cardassian
hologram is on line,
that's exactly
what you're doing.
It's not that simple.
It is to me.
Crell Moset killed thousands
of people in his hospitals.
As long as we're willing
to benefit from his research,
we're no better than he is.
If I had weeks, or even days,
maybe I could come up
with an alternative,
but time is of the essence
and Moset's idea will work.
Then you've got
to use it.
Even if the Doctor
could perform the surgery
without Moset's help,
he'd still be using
the man's research.
That would be going
against B'Elanna's wishes.
We're talking about
a woman who has
alien tendrils
sapping the life out of her.
She's obviously
not thinking straight.
On the contrary.
Her concerns are based in logic.
( scoffing ):
Logic?
If the Doctor uses knowledge
that Moset gained
through his experiments,
we would be validating
his methods, inviting
further unethical research.
We'd be setting
a terrible precedent.
We're in the middle
of the Delta Quadrant.
Who would know?
We would know.
Fine.
Let's just deactivate
the evil hologram
and let B'Elanna die.
At least, we'd have
our morals intact.
Tom.
And you, Chakotay,
since when do you care
what Starfleet thinks?
This isn't about rules
and regulations.
This is about doing
what's right.
Spoken like a true Maquis.
Well, if you'd just
set aside your hatred
of the Cardassian
for one second...
Enough, Lieutenant.
All right, all right.
The arguments have been made
and we're running out of time.
The fact is, you're both right.
But when it comes down to it,
the only issue
I'm concerned about
is the well-being of that
crew member lying in Sick Bay.
We'll wrestle with the morality
of this situation later--
after B'Elanna is
back on her feet.
Doctor, you have
my authorization to proceed
with Moset's assistance.
Yes, Captain.
Any consequences
of this decision
will be my responsibility.
Dismissed.
Thanks.
MOSET:
Scalpel.
Ensign Kim,
do you hear something?
Hear what?
A series of
high frequencies.
They are getting louder.
Must be those Vulcan
ears of yours.
( high-pitched alien language)
I hear it, too.
Anything on sensors?
( alien language gets louder)
It appears to be
an alien com signal.
Triaxilating wavelengths.
Origins?
Unknown.
( signal getting very loud )
KIM:
Captain, a vessel just
dropped out of warp.
Approaching fast
off the port bow.
On screen.
( loud signal continues )
CHAKOTAY:
Can we dampen
it a little?
Negative.
( signal stops )
Harry, tell me that was just
their way of saying hello.
I wish I could.
The universal translator
doesn't have a clue.
Perhaps they are waiting
for our response.
Well, then,
let's give them one.
Open a channel,
all subspace bands.
This is Captain Janeway of
the Federation Starship Voyager.
We cannot interpret
your message,
but please try to understand,
we are on a peaceful mission
and we intend you no harm.
We have one of your kind
on board our ship.
It's injured and we're
attempting to provide treatment.
If you can understand...
( loud, screeching
alien language )
MOSET:
I'm ready to stimulate
the primary neural pathways.
Cortical probe.
I'm applying it
to the primary neocortex.
( shrieking )
Its motor control
is weakening,
but not enough to
release the patient.
Our little friend
needs a bigger jolt.
I'm increasing the
pulse frequency...
( shrieking )
The synapses
are degenerating.
You're killing it.
Don't lose your
nerve, Doctor--
not when we're
this close.
Lower the pulse
frequency.
If I do that, the creature
will regain control.
I don't care.
Lower the pulse.
Doctor...
Lower the pulse frequency
or I'll take
your program off-line.
You realize you're reducing
our chances of saving her?
Not necessarily.
Give me the probe.
The probe, Doctor.
If we apply the pulse
to the secondary neocortex,
we should be able to
achieve the same results
at a lower frequency.
Not particularly
efficient.
But it might prove
interesting.
I'm reading an energy surge
in their forward section.
( rumbling )
Shields!
Doctor to Bridge.
The holodeck's going off-line.
What's happening up there?
Stand by, Doctor.
They've locked on to us
with some sort of tractor beam.
It's draining our power.
CHAKOTAY:
Reroute emergency power
to the holodeck.
Send an antimatter surge
through the shield matrix.
See if that'll
loosen their grip.
No effect.
We do have weapons.
No. If they wanted
to destroy us,
they wouldn't be using
a tractor beam.
They're trying to rescue
their crew member.
Captain...
This isn't about logic, Tuvok.
It's about instinct.
Now, I may not speak
their language,
but I have a gut feeling
they don't want an armed
conflict any more than we do.
Bridge to Doctor.
What's your status?
The procedure's working.
Almost there, Captain.
It's losing motor control.
The tendrils are withdrawing
from her lungs,
liver, kidneys...
( alarm bleeping )
The alien's life signs
are failing.
We need a substitute
for the metabolic energy
it was taking from B'Elanna.
Could we restore
its own metabolism?
Perhaps. Give it
40 milligrams of stenophyl.
It's going
into anaphylactic shock.
All right. Increasing
the dosage to 60 milligrams...
We've lost power
on Decks 7 through 12.
Shields are failing,
Captain.
Doctor?
Stand by, Captain.
Anaphylaxia
is subsiding.
Its electrolytic reactions
are increasing.
Its metabolism is
stabilizing on its own.
Bridge, beam the life-form
to its ship.
Transport complete.
The alien ship is
withdrawing, Captain.
( alien signal resumes )
You're welcome.
I've released B'Elanna
to her quarters.
Her condition?
Stable, but her nervous system
has suffered extreme trauma.
She'll need time to recover--
several days, at least.
Good work.
I should caution you, Captain--
when I told her
that we'd used Moset's program,
she was unhappy,
to put it mildly.
I nearly had to sedate her.
It sounds like her Klingon
temper has fully recovered.
It practically qualifies
as a chronic condition.
( sighing ):
I'll speak to her.
There's one more topic
of concern.
Should we delete the program
or keep Moset in our database
for future emergencies?
I'm inclined to leave
this up to you, Doctor.
You are the Chief Medical
Officer on this ship.
As far as I'm concerned,
there's no one
more qualified than you
to make that decision.
Thank you, Captain.
But please make it quickly.
I'm eager to resolve
this matter.
There's been enough
moral controversy
on this ship for one day.
( door chimes )
Come in.
At ease.
Interesting fragrance.
I'm surprised
it hasn't set off
the environmental alarms.
It's a combination
of mental relaxant
and expeller of demons.
It's an ancient Klingon remedy.
Feeling any better?
I'm alive.
I hope you can understand
why I went against
your wishes, B'Elanna.
Losing you
was unacceptable.
I know you're angry, but we
need to put this behind us.
Understood?
Is that an order?
Yes.
You can't order someone to get
rid of an emotion, Captain.
And what emotion is that?
You had no right
to make that decision for me!
I'm the Captain.
You're my crewman.
I did what I thought best.
I get the feeling there are
still a few demons in the air.
Let's hope this does
the trick, hmm?
( humming )
Doc...
how's our patient?
Recuperating.
( sighing ):
We did it.
Yes... we did.
A celebration is in order.
How about listening
to that opera
you promised me?
Oh, you're, uh...
still wrestling with
your ethical subroutines.
Take my advice.
It's a waste of time.
What's important is that
we saved two lives today.
I'm not concerned with today.
It's tomorrow I'm worried about.
Captain Janeway has left
your future in my hands.
She believes that,
as Voyager's Chief
Medical Officer,
it's up to me to decide
whether your program
remains in our database.
Personally, I predict a long
and fruitful collaboration
between us.
Oh?
Think about
what we accomplished
in the last 24 hours.
Our first case was a triumph.
Both patients are thriving
and we advanced the frontiers
of medical science.
I've already outlined a paper
that you and I
will one day present
to the Federation
Medical Academy:
"Total Systemic Invasion
of a Klingon-human Hybrid
By a Cytoplasmic
Pseudo-parasite."
Has a nice ring to it,
don't you think?
Are we also going to tell them
where you honed
your surgical techniques?
A footnote, perhaps--
"For further details,
see Cardassian death camps."
Those techniques
were crucial this morning.
Where was your sarcasm then?
I didn't come here to debate
the issue with you, Crell.
I came here to inform you
of my decision.
"It is my judgment that
the Medical Consultant Program
"and all the algorithms
contained therein
"shall be deleted
from the database.
"In light of
recent evidence,
"I cannot in good conscience
utilize research
that was derived
from such inhuman practices."
"In good conscience"?
What about the well-being
of your crew?
You're confronted by
new forms of life every day--
many of them dangerous.
You need me.
Delete my program
and you violate the first oath
you took as a physician:
"Do no harm."
"Do no harm..." you have
no right to say those words.
Computer...
You can erase my program,
Doctor,
but you can never
change the fact
that you've already used
some of my research.
Where was your conscience
when B'Elanna was dying
on that table?
Ethics? Morality?
Conscience?
Funny how they all go
out the airlock
when we need something.
Are you and I
really so different?
Computer, delete
Medical Consultant Program
and all related files.