( serene theme playing )
Lieutenant Thomas
Eugene Paris,
I hereby reduce you
to the rank of Ensign.
And I sentence you to 30
days solitary confinement.
Take Ensign Paris
to the brig.
I know the way.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Brig.
( sighs )
( melancholy theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )
( sighs )
( clears throat )
( gasps )
One... two... three...
( door opens )
98... 99... 100.
Staying in shape?
Oh, yeah.
I do it every time
I'm in jail.
Well, I hope
all that exercise
gave you an appetite.
Leola root stew again?
That's the third time
this week.
Can't you just
replicate me a pizza?
Sorry, Tom.
Basic nutrition only.
Captain's orders.
Ah, bread and water, huh?
Let's have it.
I got you the PADD
you asked for.
Oh... thanks.
So...
did you ask the warden
about those holodeck privileges?
Uh, she said,
and I quote:
"Tell Mr. Paris this is
punishment, not shore leave."
( dry chuckle )
It was worth a try.
Well, see you next meal.
Wait, leaving already?
Uh, pull up a chair.
Stay awhile.
Sorry. No nonessential
conversation with the prisoner.
( frustrated sigh )
Do the words "cruel and unusual"
mean anything to her?
I'm telling you,
Neelix,
the inmates are getting
restless.
She's going to have a full-blown
prison riot on her hands.
( sighing )
( door opens, closes )
Begin letter.
Dear Father...
pause... and erase.
Begin.
To Admiral Paris...
pause... and erase.
Begin.
Hey, Dad...
Long time, no see.
Chances are you'll never
receive this letter...
but in case you do, there's
a few things I wanted to say.
First of all...
bad news.
Um... I'm in jail again.
Wait! Keep listening.
Don't turn this off.
I want you to know
how I ended up in here...
because...
it's not what you think.
It all started on a morning
I was doing something
you would find
a complete waste of time.
( triumphant theme playing )
Captain Proton
to Buster Kincaid.
I've destroyed Dr. Chaotica's
mind control machine
and I'm on my way back
to the spaceship.
FEMALE:
Hello, Proton.
Who is this?
An old friend.
Make that two old friends.
PROTON:
The Twin Mistresses of Evil...
I should have known.
I'm afraid your
trusty sidekick
is indisposed
at the moment.
Don't worry about me, Captain. I
can handle myself.
We'll see
about that.
Bring me the
brain probe.
The what?
The brain probe,
you insolent fool.
Oh, right.
Your wish is
my command.
Sorry, Harry.
No problem.
Torture me all
you want, Demonica.
I'll never crack.
Oh, but you will.
By the time
we're through with you,
you'll be begging to tell us
everything you know.
You'll be our puppet.
Our slave.
Great. You're
doing great.
You're done for, Demonica.
Malicia.
She's Demonica.
Whatever.
You two are going to jail
for a very long time.
Ooh.
Move it, toots.
He's so brave.
It's a shame
we'll have to kill him.
I've got everything
under control, Proton.
Shouldn't you be
getting back to headquarters?
And leave you at the
mercy of these two?
Come on, Tom. I'm just
getting to the good part.
CHAKOTAY:
Senior officers,
report to the Bridge.
I guess the good part
will have to wait.
Any progress
on those star charts?
I'll have them
to you by 1400.
1400? You told me they'd
be done yesterday.
I'm sorry, Tom.
The sensor array
went off-line.
Seven of Nine will have it up
and running this morning.
1400, I promise.
You need some help?
I'm not on duty again
till tomorrow morning.
No, I don't want to
spoil your day off.
Oh, I don't mind.
Thanks, anyway.
See you later, Lieutenant.
Buster.
Bye.
( sighs )
I think Jenny
really likes you.
Yeah, I know.
I thought the
feeling was mutual.
How many times do
I have to tell you?
I like Megan, but she won't
give me the time of day.
Ha, ha. What
is the difference?
You can't
be serious.
They're the Delaney sisters,
Harry. They're twins.
Are you kidding?
They're nothing alike.
Jenny's aggressive,
and sometimes annoying,
but Megan--
she's quiet, artistic,
and she's got that cute little
dimple in her right cheek.
Jenny doesn't have the dimple?
( door opens )
No dimple.
Hmm.
( door closes )
Bridge.
Well, you've done it
again, Harry.
What?
Fallen for
the unattainable woman.
First it was a hologram,
then a Borg,
and now, the wrong twin.
At least I'm consistent.
( chuckling )
( soft theme playing )
Sorry to interrupt
your fun, gentlemen,
but long-range sensors
have picked up
something interesting.
A concentrated mass
of oxygen and hydrogen.
Lots of animal
and plant life.
An M-Class planet?
No.
That's the interesting part.
TUVOK:
We're entering
visual range.
On screen.
( soft theme playing )
KIM:
What is it?
It's an ocean.
According to these readings,
it's bigger than the Atlantic
and Pacific combined.
What's holding it
together?
Looks like there's some
sort of a containment field
keeping it from
dissipating.
Take us in closer, Tom.
Are those starships
or submarines?
Open a channel.
This is Captain Janeway
of the Starship Voyager.
Please identify yourselves.
They are powering weapons.
Shields.
( rumbling )
Red Alert.
TUVOK:
Shields holding. No damage.
Should I return fire?
Not yet.
Voyager to approaching vessels.
We have no hostile intentions.
They're maintaining
their course.
Target the lead ship
and take out their weapons.
( dramatic theme playing )
Direct hit.
They're hailing.
I guess we got their attention.
On screen.
I'm Deputy Consul Burkus
of the Monean
Maritime Sovereignty.
You violated our space.
Withdraw
or we'll resume firing.
Consul, we could have destroyed
your ships, but we didn't.
We have no interest in a fight.
Then why are you here?
Because we're explorers
and we're fascinated
by your ocean,
and we'd like to learn
more about it
and your people,
if you'd be willing.
And if we are not?
We'll be disappointed,
but we'll leave you alone.
Your ship's impressive.
Well, I'd be happy
to give you a tour.
Forgive our
vigilance, Captain.
Over the years,
my government
has had to
protect our ocean
from more than one
hostile species.
I understand.
We're also very protective
of our own natural resources.
NEELIX:
...about new cultures.
Yours sounds
particularly fascinating.
JANEWAY:
And this is Voyager's
command center.
Feel free to have
a look around.
NEELIX:
I'm curious, Consul.
Have your people
always lived here?
Our ancestors
were nomadic.
They only discovered
the waters 300 years ago.
I'll bet they were
as stunned as we were
to find this huge ball of
water floating in space.
Yes. Mister...?
Paris. Tom Paris.
JANEWAY:
My First Officer,
Commander Chakotay.
They realized they could
farm sea vegetation,
extract oxygen
from the ocean
for their ships...
create a permanent home.
What's your population?
More than 80,000.
And you all
live underwater?
TUVOK:
Lieutenant,
we do have
other business
to attend to.
Mr. Tuvok, escort our guests
to the briefing room.
( soft theme playing )
Care to join us,
Mr. Paris?
How could you tell?
Do you still live
aboard your ships?
We've built an industrial
infrastructure
and undersea dwellings,
but yes, most of our people
still choose to live
as our ancestors did.
Any idea how the ocean
came into existence?
In my experience,
it's a unique phenomenon.
Riga?
There are
several theories.
Our clerics teach
that the ocean
was a divine gift
from the creators
to protect
and sustain us,
but, in my opinion, the most
plausible explanation is
that the ocean formed naturally,
much the same way
that a gas giant does.
Makes sense.
RIGA:
Unfortunately,
our limited knowledge
of the phenomenon has created
a few problems.
What do you mean?
BURKUS:
I'm not sure
this is
an appropriate topic.
But they might be able
to help us.
JANEWAY:
We'll do anything we can.
The ocean's losing
containment.
Hydro-volume has decreased
more than seven percent
in the last year alone.
Any idea what's causing it?
No. To make a thorough study,
we'd need to explore
the ocean's center
where I believe
the gravitational currents
are fluctuating.
But that's more than
600 kilometers deep.
Our best research vessel
can only go 100 kilometers.
Beyond that,
the pressure's too great.
Well, we could
take you there.
Captain?
( serene theme playing )
I had no idea you were
such an old salt.
Ha. When I saw
that ocean today,
it reminded me of the first
time I read Jules Verne.
20,000 Leagues Under The Sea.
Mmm!
I must have read it
20,000 times.
I was obsessed
with stories about the ocean.
All of my friends were busy
with their holo-programs.
I had my head buried
in Captains Courageous,
Moby Dick...
So your interest
in history includes
the 19th century, as well.
Ancient sailing ships
were always my first love.
I had it all planned.
Finish high school, join
the Federation Naval Patrol...
but my father had other ideas.
You'd think Admiral Paris
might have understood
his son's passion.
Hmm...
As far as he was concerned,
the only ship
I was going to serve on
had to have
a Starfleet insignia on it.
So now you have an opportunity
to make up for lost time.
Captain...
with a few simple
thruster modifications
to the Delta Flyer, she will
be seaworthy in no time.
Good.
It'd take at least a week
to make the necessary
modifications to Voyager.
Then it's my mission?
Bon voyage.
( upbeat theme playing )
( laughs )
And so, I thought to myself,
who better than Harry
to be my first mate?
First mate?
Oh. Sailor talk. You'll
get the hang of it.
Ah.
I'm telling you, Harry,
I have been dreaming
about something like this
for as long as
I can remember.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but there is a mission
involved here, right?
Of course!
But there's no law that says
we can't have a little
fun along the way.
Ah, bosun.
Ready to shove off?
What are you talking
about, Lieutenant?
Call me Skipper.
Sailor talk.
You'll get used to it.
I think not.
Hull and thruster
reinforcements are complete.
Ah, that's what
I wanted to hear.
RIGA:
Oh, excuse me.
Am I in the right place?
Welcome aboard.
I see you like to travel light.
These are
my instruments
for measuring depth,
pressure, currents...
We will not need them.
This vessel is equipped
with a complete sensor array.
Oh.
Uh, it's okay.
You can store your gear
in the hold.
( serene theme playing )
20,000 kilometers
to the surface.
Immersion shielding?
SEVEN:
Active.
Anchors aweigh.
( serene theme playing )
Those structures,
what are they?
It's our main
oxygen refinery
and desalination plant.
Corrosion resistant alloys,
variable-density ballast...
an efficient design.
That means
she's impressed.
We're very proud
of what we've built here.
I can see why.
( sighs )
( door chimes )
Come in.
I'm afraid we have
some disturbing news.
Oh?
We've run
a computer simulation
to determine
the rate of dissipation.
It's worse than
Mr. Riga thought.
According to our estimates,
the ocean could experience
a complete loss of containment
in less than five years.
I'm sorry.
Your calculations
could be wrong.
I know it
sounds grim,
but there may be some
way to stop the process.
And if there isn't?
You might have to
consider evacuating.
I'm supposed to go back
and explain this
to 47 regional
sovereigns?
They'll pass their
first unanimous resolution...
calling for my head.
I can imagine how difficult
this must be for you...
but you will have
to tell them.
Perhaps...
but I'll wait until
your Delta Flyer returns.
Maybe they'll find
something tangible.
( suspenseful theme playing )
We're at a depth
of 560 kilometers.
( creaking )
What was that?
The hull contracting.
Rerouting additional power
to structural integrity.
Nothing to worry about.
I'm detecting multiphasic energy
discharges, bearing 021 mark 6.
Range: 12 kilometers.
A structure.
At this depth?
Adjusting course.
I can't see anything.
Give me forward
illumination, Harry.
What is it?
KIM:
It's generating
massive amounts of
artificial gravity.
Looks like
some kind of field reactor.
If it's malfunctioning,
that would explain
the loss of hydro-volume.
Maybe it can be repaired.
It looks ancient.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Well, if these readings
are right,
it's at least 100,000 years old.
We've no records
of any previous inhabitants.
Who built it?
Where did they go?
KIM:
Looks like
the reactor
is controlled by
a core computer.
I'll try to upload the database
and get some answers.
Initiate the interface.
Upload in progress.
( rumbling )
What's happening?
We've got a visitor.
What was it?
You're the one that lives here.
You tell us.
No one's ever been
this far down before.
We don't know anything
about marine life
at these depths.
You are about
to have the opportunity
to make a detailed study.
( dramatic theme playing )
( rumbling )
( grunts )
The creature's emitting
biothermic discharges.
KIM:
It's like
some kind of electric eel.
Only a hell of a lot bigger.
( rumbling )
And significantly more powerful.
That last discharge exceeded
500,000 volts.
The shields are fried, Tom.
You might want to think
about getting us
out of here.
( dramatic theme playing )
Thrusters are off-line.
Targeting forward phasers.
No, you can't kill it.
I do not intend to.
Unfortunately, the creature
does not seem to be
of a similar opinion.
How's that upload coming?
Another couple of minutes.
Firing phasers.
I think we only made him madder.
The creature is retreating.
( sighs )
( alarm blaring )
We've got a breach!
I'm on it.
( grunting )
600 kilometers underwater,
propulsion off-line,
water pouring into the cabin...
( laughs )
It was like something
out of one
of those Jules Verne stories
you used to read me
when I was a kid.
JANEWAY:
Red Alert! All hands
to battle stations.
Hey, what about me?
If we're in trouble,
we need our best pilot
at the helm.
You can't just leave me here!
( grunts )
( serene theme playing )
( groans )
Five ships?
And they just opened
fire without warning?
Mm-hmm.
Oh...
How did we get away?
Apparently, Ensign Culhane
confused the enemy
with a brilliant series
of evasive maneuvers.
I hear Captain Janeway
is considering him
for Chief Conn Officer.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you just
tell the Captain
that Culhane's
brilliant maneuvers
almost knocked
me unconscious. Aah.
You'd think he'd never
flown a shuttle,
much less a starship.
There we are.
That's it?
Aren't you going to run
a neurological scan?
Maybe I should be granted
a medical reprieve.
Your injury was what Naomi
Wildman refers to as a boo-boo.
Come on, Doc. You don't
understand what it's like
being down here
all day, every day.
I'm going crazy.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but isn't that the idea?
No, seriously, doc,
you might want
to take me down
to Sickbay for a full
psychiatric evaluation.
Three or four days
of observation at least.
See you in 20 days.
Doc!
( sighing )
( suspenseful theme playing )
Resume recording.
Okay, Dad, where were we?
Ah, right.
We had just sprung a leak.
( soft theme playing )
Nothing like a cold shower
to wake up the senses.
Structural integrity
is weakening.
We've lost communications,
shields, propulsion.
We can reduce our density
by venting plasma
and transporting
all nonessential equipment
off the ship.
It will take time, but we will
eventually rise to the surface.
I think we should stay.
Stay?
I'm not about to be scared off
by a few damaged systems.
KIM:
Tom, don't you think
maybe you're carrying
this Captains Courageous thing
a little too far?
Look...
it's a good bet that the
reactor's malfunctioning.
Now, we're only going to get
one shot at fixing it.
You want to leave, fine.
Give me an environmental suit
and you can pick me up
after you've repaired the Flyer.
You're going for a swim?
Are you crazy?
You have a better idea?
Well...
we already managed to interface
with the reactor's computer.
Maybe we can make the repairs,
maybe we can't,
but I'm not leaving you
down here alone.
What about you two?
I'll stay.
Seven?
It is in my nature
to comply with the collective.
( suspenseful theme playing )
I'm detecting a breach
in the containment field.
Any way we
can seal it?
We might try reinforcing
the field
with a deflector beam.
Do it. Try hailing
the Delta Flyer again.
CHAKOTAY:
Nothing.
What do you
think's happened?
They may be too deep
to receive a transmission.
They may have
had an accident.
It's possible.
Possible?
Captain, I'll need a better
explanation than that.
What am I supposed
to tell the Council?
Clarify something for me.
Are you more concerned
about the lives
of the people on that shuttle
or your political career?
What's that?
SEVEN:
A gravimetric discharge.
The reactor's core is unstable.
You'd be unstable, too, if you
were as old as this thing.
Age has nothing to do with it.
The reactor's diverting
massive amounts of power
to its structural
integrity field,
power normally reserved
for oceanic containment.
That would explain why
containment is weakening.
KIM:
Looks like the density
of the water's been increasing
over the past few years.
It seems the reactor's
just trying
to keep itself
from being crushed.
( rumbling )
Can we initiate a power
transfer, stabilize the core?
I believe so, but it would be
a temporary solution.
It's better than nothing.
( suspenseful theme playing )
Captain, full containment
has just been re-established.
The deflector beam.
Negative. The ocean appears
to have been stabilized
from within.
It looks like our
team has succeeded.
I'm picking up an object
on a slow ascent.
It's the Flyer.
You found something?
I've been studying
the generator's database.
You're not going
to believe this,
but apparently, your ocean
used to be part of a landmass.
Really?
As far as I can tell,
it was part
of a planetary ecosystem
inhabited by
a very advanced civilization.
What happened
to them?
That's a good question.
All I know is they launched
this reactor
into orbit.
They used
some kind
of elaborate
kinetic transfer system
to draw the water and everything
in it up to the reactor.
Extraordinary.
Why would anyone want to move
an entire ocean?
Maybe there was some kind
of disaster on the planet,
or maybe it was
just an experiment.
That must have been
a massive undertaking.
Took them almost 200 years.
I wonder what they'd think
if they knew we settled here
and built another civilization.
Actually, I think
they'd be pretty concerned.
Oh?
This field reactor
that they designed--
it's a pretty amazing piece
of technology-- durable...
I don't think it's responsible
for the loss of containment.
But as soon as we made
the recalibration,
the water stabilized.
I don't see what
else it could be.
Riga, your mining operations
are destroying the ocean.
( suspenseful theme playing )
ADMIRAL PARIS:
You'll never get
into Starfleet Academy
by playing with toys.
Do your homework.
Are you listening to me,
Thomas?
JANEWAY:
Thomas Eugene Paris,
I hereby reduce you
to the rank of Ensign.
And I sentence you to 30 years
in solitary confinement.
ADMIRAL PARIS:
Go to your room, young man.
That's an order.
Stay there and think
about what I've said.
KIM ( whispering ):
Tom...
Tom, wake up.
( gasps )
Bad dream?
Oh...
You could say that.
You know,
you look like hell.
Ha. Thanks.
How'd you get
past the guard?
The Vulcan neck pinch.
Come to spring me?
Well, the Captain finally
gave me permission to visit,
but I've only got
a few minutes.
That's big of her.
How are you doing?
Oh, 30 days?
No problem.
How's B'Elanna?
She misses you.
Yeah. I know
the feeling.
So, what have you been doing
to pass the time?
Ha. Thinking
and...
thinking. Ha.
Trying not to think.
Actually, I started recording
a letter to my father.
Really?
Yeah.
For some reason, I...
I wanted to explain to him
how I ended up in here.
I didn't want
him to think...
Well, anyway, I realized
how ridiculous it was.
You should finish it.
Give me one
good reason.
Maybe he'll hear it someday.
Doubtful.
You'll feel better
getting it off your chest.
Are you bucking for
ship's counselor, Harry?
What are you going to do,
delete the letter?
That would be pointless.
At least I'm
consistent.
Tom...
Thanks for the
visit, Harry.
See you in 14.
( suspenseful theme playing )
What was it
you once told me?
That your father used to say
you never finished anything?
( door opens and closes )
( sighs )
( serene theme playing )
PARIS:
Resume recording.
So, we told Consul Burkus
about the alien field reactor
and how his oxygen refineries
were destroying it.
He took the news pretty well...
at first.
The Council's very grateful
for your help, Captain.
They've asked me
to request
the shield
and thruster schematics
for your Delta Flyer.
We're hoping
to design a probe
that'll allow us
to monitor
the containment
generator.
Lieutenant Torres
will give you
everything you need.
I've also drawn up some designs
for an oxygen
replication system.
It'll allow you to
create free oxygen
without extricating
it from the water.
It won't solve your problems
overnight,
but it's a start.
I'm sure it'll be
very helpful.
Our oxygen extraction levels
are still dangerously high.
I'm going to recommend
shutting down refineries
four, five and six.
We'll take it
under advisement. Well...
Captain, I wish you
a safe journey.
Well, we have
a few more suggestions,
if you'd like to hear them.
Please... pass them along
to Mr. Riga.
He'll include them
in his report.
PARIS:
I'm curious.
Who's going to read that report?
It will be given
to the subcommittees
on life support and agriculture.
RIGA:
Excuse me, Consul,
I'm not sure you understand
the magnitude of the crisis.
What you're suggesting
could take months.
Thank you, Mr. Riga.
You should listen to him.
If you don't make some serious
changes around here soon,
that ocean won't be here
much longer.
As I said,
we understand his concerns.
Do you? It seems to me
like you're just trying
to sidestep the issue
and send us on our way.
With all due respect,
who are you
to tell us what to do
with our ocean?
With all due respect,
it's not your ocean.
Lieutenant.
It's all right, Captain.
I'd like to respond,
but not as a diplomat
as a Monean.
You came here claiming
you wanted to learn
about our way of life,
and now, having spent
three days here,
you're suggesting
we abandon it.
We have an expression--
brine in the veins.
Tell him what it means.
It's used to describe someone
who has a special connection
to the waters.
My family has lived here
for ten generations.
We protected this ocean,
cultivated it,
lived in harmony with
the animals that inhabit it.
Can you say the same?
I didn't think so.
Good day, Captain.
( door opens )
( door closes )
We can't just let this go.
What do you want me to do?
( scoffs )
Of course.
The almighty Prime Directive.
Would you please excuse us,
Lieutenant.
See you later.
I know you're
upset, Lieutenant,
but when you're
in a room with me,
you check that attitude
at the door. Understood?
Captain--
We can't expect
an entire society
to change because we
think they should.
Then you agree with me.
Yes.
And we gave them the
help they asked for.
We told them what we know.
Now it's up to them to do
what they think
is appropriate.
You heard that consul.
They're not going to do
a damn thing.
Maybe not, but that's
their prerogative.
Captain--
End of discussion, Lieutenant.
At 1400 hours,
we'll resume a course
for the Alpha Quadrant.
Is that clear?
As a bell.
( soft theme playing )
( holodeck door opens )
Hey.
Here to stamp out
intergalactic evil?
( chuckling )
It's funny.
What?
I went on this mission
expecting to play out
a childhood fantasy,
but along the way,
when I realized that ocean
would just be...gone one day...
it started
to matter to me.
( chuckles )
Sounds pretty stupid, huh?
No.
No, it sounds like you've
found yourself a cause.
( chuckles )
I never thought of myself
as a cause kind of guy.
Well, for what it's worth,
I'm proud of you.
Thanks.
( sighs )
But Captain Proton's
not going to be able
to save the day
this time, is he?
What about Tom Paris?
( soft theme playing )
Council Chamber, please.
Riga...
You're dismissed, crewman.
I want you
to tell me honestly--
what do you think's
going to happen now?
I think the bureaucracy
isn't going to make
more than token changes.
Isn't there anything else
you can do?
I don't see how.
Other than taking the oxygen
refineries off-line.
What would happen--
hypothetically--
if someone were to shut down
the refineries?
Well, I suppose
they'd have to be rebuilt.
Yeah, and they'd probably
be more willing
to redesign them
while they're at it.
If nothing else,
it would grab their attention.
Are you suggesting...?
I'm just asking questions...
because I'm not supposed
to get involved
in the internal affairs
of alien worlds...
unless, of course,
someone makes a direct request.
( suspenseful theme playing )
If you can get me down there,
I'd be willing to do it.
You'd be risking your life.
I know.
Captain, there
has just been
an unauthorized launch
from Shuttle Bay 1--
the Delta Flyer.
Tom.
( suspenseful theme swells )
Hail him.
No response.
Try a tractor beam.
We're out of range.
We're being hailed, Captain.
It's Consul Burkus.
Your shuttlecraft
has violated our borders.
I demand an explanation.
Mr. Paris is acting
without authorization.
To what end?
According to our scans,
Mr. Riga is with him.
I have to assume they intend
to take some sort of...
radical action
to protect the ocean.
Then I presume
you intend to take
radical action to stop them.
( suspenseful theme playing )
( metal creaking )
COMPUTER:
Warning. Hull pressure
approaching critical.
We're going down too fast.
It's the only way we
can outrun your ships.
Janeway to Paris.
Return to Voyager immediately.
I'm sorry, Captain.
I can't do that.
Lieutenant, you are disobeying
a direct order.
I know.
He cut us off.
What the hell are they up to?
KIM:
Looks like
they're heading
directly beneath
the industrial complex.
Can we reach them
with phasers?
TUVOK:
Unadvisable.
It would create
a hydro-dynamic shock wave.
What about an old-fashioned
depth charge?
It should be possible
to modify a photon torpedo.
We could program
it to detonate
once it's in proximity
to the Delta Flyer.
Do it.
( suspenseful theme playing )
The torpedo is ready, Captain.
However,
the Delta Flyer
has submerged
below our
targeting range.
Consul Burkus,
hailing again.
On screen.
Our refinery workers
have been given five minutes
to clear the structure.
Was this the kind of evacuation
you had in mind, Captain?
Can you get them out in time?
Yes, but...
Do it. I'll find a way
to protect your refinery.
End transmission.
Captain!
TUVOK:
He descended
to avoid attack.
If my calculations
are correct,
he will have to come back up
to a depth of 2,000 meters
to strike his target.
Giving us a window
of opportunity.
Precisely.
Captain, this is Tom
we're talking about.
We're not going
to open fire, are we?
As far as I'm concerned,
he forfeited his status
as a protected member
of this crew
the second he launched
that shuttle.
How long till we reach
our target?
36 seconds.
( console beeps )
He's started his ascent.
JANEWAY: Hail him.
KIM: Go ahead.
Lieutenant Paris,
this is your final warning.
He's not responding.
Arm the torpedo.
20 seconds to weapons range.
Are you sure you want
to go through with this?
You?
I've taken you this far.
We better arm that missile.
Missile armed.
JANEWAY:
Stand down, Mr. Paris,
or I will open fire.
Still no answer.
Time.
Ten seconds.
Nine...
Eight... seven...
six...
Five...
four... three...
Two... one.
Fire.
Fire!
( dramatic theme playing )
( rumbling )
The Flyer has
been disabled.
Their missile?
Deflected.
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log,
Stardate 52179.4.
After salvaging
the Delta Flyer,
we've resumed our course
toward the Alpha Quadrant.
I now have to turn my attention
to a matter of discipline.
Lieutenant Thomas
Eugene Paris,
you are guilty
of insubordination,
unauthorized use
of a spacecraft,
reckless endangerment
and conduct unbecoming
an officer.
Do you have
anything to say?
Riga needed my help.
In doing so, you disobeyed
my direct orders.
Yes, ma'am.
You violated the protocols
that govern this crew.
Yes, ma'am.
You nearly caused an armed
conflict with the Moneans.
And frankly, you're lucky to
be standing here right now.
I would have destroyed
your shuttle if necessary.
Yes, ma'am.
Permission to speak freely.
Riga's people
weren't going to listen.
They were going
to ignore our warnings.
You don't know that.
Riga knew, and I was the only
one who could help them.
I understand your passion,
but passion alone
doesn't give you the right
to take matters
into your own hands.
Four years ago,
I released you
from prison and gave
you a fresh start.
Until now, you've been
a fine officer.
Your service on this ship
has been exemplary.
I really believed you were
past this kind of conduct.
I've never been very good
at playing by the rules.
That doesn't mean
that serving under your command
hasn't changed me--
for the better.
At least this time,
I broke the rules for a reason,
for something I believed in.
I admire your
principles, Tom,
but I can't ignore
what you've done.
I hereby reduce you
to the rank of Ensign.
And I sentence you
to 30 days solitary confinement.
Take Ensign Paris
to the brig.
I know the way.
Rise and shine, Ensign.
Your 30 days
have been served.
You may want
to shave first.
Yes, sir.
Torres to Paris.
Go ahead.
Rumor has it that
you're free for dinner.
Ha. Gee, I don't know.
Are you sure you want to be seen
associating with an ex-con?
My quarters, 0700.
That's an order, Ensign.
Yes, ma'am.
Resume recording.
Well, I'm out now
and back to my duties.
( soft theme playing )
I honestly don't know
if I'll ever understand you,
or what went wrong between us,
but I hope this letter helps you
understand me a little better.
Computer, file letter
in my personal database...
and transmit when we're
within range of Earth.
( melancholy theme playing )
( majestic theme playing )