ANNOUNCER:
The Adventures of Captain Proton
Chapter 18:
"Bride of Chaotica."
The evil Dr. Chaotica
kidnaps Constance Goodheart
and plans to sacrifice her
to Arachnia,
Queen of the Spider People.
( screaming shrilly )
( laughing )
Captain Proton travels
millions of miles to Planet X,
where he will invade
the Fortress of Doom.
Chaotica fires
his fiendish death ray--
certain death for Proton,
as his rocket ship
bursts into flames.
We didn't burst into flames
in the last chapter.
Why are these recaps
always so inaccurate?
Well, they brought people
back to the theaters.
Cliffhangers.
The lost art
of hyperbole.
You ready?
Aye, Captain.
Let's get this
show on the road.
Computer...
begin Chapter 18.
( computer beeping )
We're receiving a transmission.
It's Chaotica.
Imagizing.
( screaming shrilly )
Captain Proton...
surrender!
Not a chance.
Release
Miss Goodheart
and we'll be
on our way.
I'm afraid your "secretary"
has already been promised
to Queen Arachnia
as a supreme sacrifice.
( screaming )
You'll never
get away with this.
Oh, ho-ho-ho!
But I shall!
You escaped
from my death ray once,
but you won't survive this!
He's charging the weapon.
Brace for impact.
( rumbling )
Direct hit!
We lost
both engines!
PARIS:
Steering jets
are on the fritz!
We're going down!
The landing gear
is jammed!
Hang on!
( crashing and thumping )
Opening hatch.
Welcome to Planet X.
What's the plan?
This is the part
where we defeat
Chaotica's soldiers,
steal their uniforms,
and make our way
through the underground caverns.
Hey, I thought you said
there were slave girls
in this chapter.
After we infiltrate
the Fortress of Doom,
we'll free
Chaotica's harem.
Let's go.
I'm right behind you.
Planet X looks
kind of familiar.
What was the last
place we went to?
The Mines of Mercury.
They're identical.
Sets were expensive.
At least there's no
erupting volcano this time.
Ah, behold the Fortress of Doom.
And how are we supposed
to get up there?
I told you-- the...
underground caverns.
Underground caverns.
Right.
I thought you said
there was no volcano.
I did.
Uh...
Tom.
Definitely
not Chaotica.
Computer,
end program.
Unable to comply.
Holodeck controls are off-line.
Paris to Bridge.
Bridge, respond.
We need to find
the manual overrides.
There's an access port
on the rocket ship.
Come on.
Report.
We dropped
out of warp.
We're at
a dead stop.
Cause?
Unknown.
Engines are operational.
( rumbling )
CHAKOTAY:
I'm reading
gravimetric forces
around the ship.
They're disrupting
our power flow.
Control systems
are going off-line.
I no longer
have access
to communications,
deflector, weapons...
Scan for vessels,
tractor beams...
anything that might explain
what's holding us here.
Halt in the name
of Chaotica!
Proton!
Buddy of yours?
Surprised?
You thought I perished
in the Den of Crocodiles.
We don't have time
for this.
I survived...
clinging to the thought
that I would
one day...
( melodramatic groaning )
Oh! Oh.
I believe I have an explanation.
Sensors show that we've
entered a layer of subspace.
It's disrupting our warp field.
Do we have impulse?
Yes.
Engage at full.
No change in our position.
Route all available power
to the engines.
We're not moving.
The impulse reactor
is running hot.
We're heading
for an overload.
Give it all she's got.
Full thrusters.
No effect.
Reactor's
at critical.
Abort.
Increase power to
the structural integrity field.
We may be here awhile.
It's no use.
I can't disengage
the program.
Well, you better think
of something fast, Proton.
A second distortion
just appeared.
Whatever they are,
they're getting bigger.
Hold on.
I've got access
to the transporter.
I'm going to try
a site-to-site.
There's a third one.
SEVEN:
I've run
a transpectral analysis.
The barrier between normal space
and subspace is unstable
throughout
this region.
Basically, we've run aground
on a subspace sandbar.
I've tried realigning
the warp field,
reversing hull
polarity...
Maybe we should just
get out and push.
SEVEN:
The gravimetric forces
are disrupting
our control systems.
As long as
we're trapped here,
we won't have access
to the computer core,
tactical, holodecks,
and all but six replicators.
What about those distortions
on the holodeck?
What's the connection?
Random
energy fluctuations.
I don't believe
they pose a threat.
Let's keep an eye
on them, anyway.
And evacuate that deck
just to be safe.
A few years back,
when I was a science
officer on the Al-Batani,
we tried to navigate
a dense protonebula.
It stopped us
dead in our tracks.
For three days, we attempted
to force our way out
until we realized
we were trying too hard.
Captain?
Every time we engaged
the engines,
we were increasing
the resistance
of the nebula's
particle field.
We may be facing
a similar situation.
SEVEN:
Our own warp field
may be increasing
the gravimetric forces.
If we power
down the core
and use minimal
thrusters,
we might be able
to break free.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
Your plan
could work.
Now that we
have your blessing...
Let's give it a try.
( instruments beeping )
Halt, in the name
of Chaotica!
We intend no harm.
Seize them!
Lower the drawbridge.
We are bringing prisoners.
( door opens )
CHAOTICA:
Yes, yes, yes, Lonzak.
What do you want?
Your Majesty.
Where's Proton?
He, uh... escaped.
Fool!
You will pay
for your incompetence!
Seize him!
( mechanical voice):
Surrender.
But, Majesty...
I have brought prisoners.
More Earthlings?
No!
They claim
they're from another dimension.
The fifth dimension.
Bring them to me.
Identify yourself.
( laughing )
You insult me!
I am Chaotica,
Ruler of the Cosmos!
Kneel before
his Majesty!
I said kneel!
You...
have invaded my planet.
Why?
To contact other
photonic life-forms...
to learn from them.
Are you alone
or are you
the vanguard
of an invading army?
We are explorers.
I am growing weary
of this charade.
Your armies will be no match
for my space force.
We'll crush you like insects!
They are hostile.
This contact should
be terminated.
CHAOTICA:
Indeed.
Lonzak, execute them!
( shrill screaming )
Coward.
He'll learn there's
no escape from Chaotica.
Gather my space force.
Power the death ray!
At once, Majesty.
Take Miss Goodheart
to Arachnia.
Invite the queen
to join me in battle.
Together,
we will rain destruction
on the fifth dimension!
( screaming shrilly )
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've been spinning our wheels
for three days now,
and still no progress
in breaking free
of the subspace layer.
Look on the bright side--
there's only
three meals a day.
Coffee. Black.
Uh, sorry, Captain.
We lost two more
replicators this morning.
Listen to me
very carefully,
because I'm only going
to say this once.
Coffee. Black.
Yes, ma'am.
While I've got your
attention, there are...
Coffee first.
Now, what's the problem?
It's a... it's a
delicate matter.
I don't have time to play
20 questions, Neelix.
Replicators aren't the only
systems of convenience off-line.
We've only got four
functioning lavatories
for a ship of 150 people.
I see.
Needless to say, lines
are beginning to form.
If we don't get
unstuck soon,
we may have a serious
problem on our hands...
uh... especially
with the Bolians.
All but three sonic
showers are off-line, too.
In another
couple of days...
I get the idea.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain to the Bridge.
On my way.
I'm going to leave these
problems in your capable hands.
Yes, ma'am.
Now, I was thinking,
if we drew up a schedule...
Whatever it takes.
Status.
The warp core
has been powered down.
Thrusters at standby.
Okay. Let's
give it a try.
Take us out, Tom, nice and slow.
PARIS:
We're moving.
Two meters per second.
Three meters.
Steady.
Nine meters.
Ten...
Increase power
to the thrusters by 50 percent.
TORRES:
We're approaching
the subspace boundary.
25 meters per second.
Wait a minute.
We're slowing down.
19 meters per
second... 18...
Captain,
I'm reading power surges.
Source?
Unknown,
but they look
like weapons signatures.
I'm not reading
any other ships in the area.
( sighs )
We've stopped.
TUVOK:
I've localized
the weapons fire.
It's emanating
from within the ship--
Deck 6,
Holodeck 2.
Who's still
on that deck?
No one. No life signs.
There's a program running.
It's Captain Proton.
Proton?
CHAKOTAY:
Can you shut it down?
KIM:
Negative.
Control system
still malfunctioning.
Tuvok, get down there and
find out what's happening.
Well, join him.
Yes, ma'am.
It appears that
a battle took place.
Believe me, it wasn't
like this when I left.
I must have missed
a few chapters.
Holodeck programs don't
normally run by themselves.
No kidding.
She's dead.
Who is she?
Constance Goodheart.
My secretary.
This doesn't make sense.
She isn't supposed to die.
She's one of the good guys.
I'm sure you two
were very close,
but she is a
holodeck character.
A character
from 1930s Hollywood.
The good guys
never get killed.
Something's wrong here.
ROBOT ( slow and distorted):
Invaders from
the fifth... dimension.
Satan's robot.
Naturally.
Queen Arachnia...
is on her way.
Invaders from
the... fifth dimension.
Give me a hand.
If we can repair
his vocalizer,
he might be able to tell us
what's been going on.
Destroy Proton.
It looks like...
he burned out a resistor.
A what?
That's a few centuries
before deutronic circuitry.
I see. How do you propose
we repair him?
Well, first of all,
we've got to remove
this damaged tube.
No problem.
Just a few crossed wires.
Your knowledge of this
technology is most impressive.
Oh... thanks.
There. Got it.
( still distorted):
Intruders... Intruders...
Intrude...
( clearly ):
Intruder alert!
Tell us
what happened.
Invaders from
the fifth dimension!
Hey, calm down!
How did these
invaders get here?
A portal.
The fifth dimension...
There's not supposed to be
alien invaders in this story.
That's in "Captain Proton
Versus the Cosmic Creature."
Invaders
from the fifth dimension!
Those subspace distortions.
Take us to this... portal.
There.
Photonic charges--
the same signatures
as the weapons fire we detected.
The fifth dimension!
We must report this
to the Captain.
Wait. I want to check
my rocket ship first.
Excuse me?
It's got sensors.
Sort of.
Maybe they can
tell us something
Voyager's sensors can't.
I've established a visual link
with the holodeck.
The attack appears to be
originating from subspace.
Can you tell where
it's coming from?
No.
( burst of static )
What was that?
Chaotica's
death ray.
Excuse me?
Let's see if we can
get a look inside
his fortress,
find out what
he's up to.
Full power to the death ray!
Arachnia,
Queen of the Spider People...
you have not responded
to my summons. Don't...
( shuts off sound )
I don't get it.
Chaotica was
supposed to be
fighting Earth
in this chapter.
Apparently,
he's found a new enemy.
The fifth
dimension.
It seems
your infantile scenario
now poses a security risk.
It was just
supposed to be
a little harmless
entertainment.
Entertainment-- another
frivolous human endeavor.
TUVOK:
These are your sensor readings?
Telegram.
It's a message
to Captain Proton
from the President
of Earth.
"Intercepted
communications
"between Dr. Chaotica
and Arachnia. Stop.
"Chaotica at war with aliens
from fifth dimension. Stop.
Must strike now
to disable death ray."
Stop.
Please summarize
the message.
Well, it looks like...
Chaotica has captured
a couple of aliens
from the fifth dimension.
An alternate universe.
Could be. Maybe they wandered
into the holodeck
through one
of those distortions.
To participate
in a game?
Intruder!
TUVOK:
I assume
there's no locking mechanism
on the hatch.
It was a
simpler time.
Is he part
of the program?
I don't
recognize him.
Invaders!
Inv...
( loud clank )
Quiet!
( quietly ):
Invaders.
Look,
there's been a
misunderstanding.
I'm Ensign Paris
from the Starship Voyager.
This is Lieutenant Tuvok.
You have killed 53 of my people.
We haven't
killed anyone...
Ensign.
Everything you see here
is a simulation.
None of it's real.
Simulation?
A photonically-based projection.
All life is photonic.
We are not.
We are biochemical life-forms.
I'm not familiar
with biochemical.
We are carbon-based.
We live aboard a starship.
I believe we have become trapped
in a region of space
that intersects your own.
We've detected no starship...
only this planet.
This planet isn't real.
As I told you,
it's part of
a simulation.
Maybe we can help you
adjust your sensors.
You don't register
as a life-form.
You are the illusion.
We're as real as
you are. Listen...
Citizen of the fifth dimension,
you will be destroyed.
PARIS:
Wait!
Damage. Damage.
Require maintenance. Help.
Help.
Let me get
this straight.
Transdimensional aliens
have mistaken
your Captain Proton simulation
for reality.
Yes, ma'am.
And now an
armed conflict
has broken out
between these aliens
and Chaotica's
holographic army.
Yes, ma'am.
His Army of Evil.
Will someone explain why we
haven't shut down the holodeck?
We've tried. The controls
are still off-line.
We're going to have
to get through to
these aliens somehow
and explain that they're
fighting shadows.
We've tried,
but they don't believe us.
They think
that we're not real.
They can't detect Voyager,
so every time they scan us,
we seem as
artificial to them
as holographic
characters do to us.
That explains why they
haven't answered our hails.
The Doctor
is photonic.
He may be able
to persuade them.
It's worth a try.
Brief him.
In the meantime,
I think we should let
the program play out.
You're not
suggesting we wait
until this Chaotica
defeats the aliens?
No, no. I'm suggesting
that we help the aliens
to defeat Chaotica.
They think that
he's leading
some kind of hostile
invasion force.
Once that threat is
gone, it's a good bet
that they will leave and
close up their portals.
How do you propose
to defeat Chaotica?
Well, he's been
attacking the aliens
with his death ray.
It's a shame
we don't have one.
No. Forget about what
it's called, Tuvok.
In the world of
Captain Proton,
it's the most powerful
weapon that there is
and because
it's photonic,
it's lethal
to these aliens.
Now, in Chapter 18,
Captain Proton
disables this weapon
just before Chaotica can use it
to destroy Earth.
And you think
that Proton,
namely you of course,
could still do that?
Well, we'd have to knock out
the lightning shield first.
A force field.
Yeah. Now you're catching on.
The destructo beam
on my rocket ship
can disable the death ray,
but only if someone gets inside
the Fortress of Doom
and can shut down
the lightning shield.
And who's supposed
to do that?
Arachnia,
Queen of the Spider People.
Charming.
Chaotica thinks so.
In the story,
he's in love with her.
He's been trying
to form an alliance
since Chapter Three.
She's the only one
that he trusts,
the only one
who can get close enough
to disable
the lightning shield.
Somebody is going to have
to take on her character.
Who'd you have in mind?
Oh, no.
It's the role
of a lifetime.
Captain, need I remind you
that we have exhausted
all other possibilities
of escaping
this layer of subspace.
Until we
can eliminate
those distortions,
we're trapped.
Think of it
as Starfleet's
first encounter
with Planet X.
Thanks.
Captain, it won't
be so bad.
I can explain to you
what you can expect.
I can tell you...
All right, all right!
I'm a size four.
What's the emergency?
I've been enlisted.
I'm supposed to make contact
with our photonic friends
from the fifth dimension
and convince them
to call off their attack.
Congratulations.
Why do you need me?
It's an undercover mission.
I'll need a bit
of cosmetic surgery.
These are the parameters
for my new costume.
What are you
going as--
the Emperor of
the Universe?
Well, I've been forced
to scale back my role
in the interest
of credibility.
I'll be President
of Earth.
I must say, the idea
of an entire universe
populated by photonic beings
is rather appealing.
Well, if your
mission fails,
you could be taking up
permanent residence.
Kim to Sick Bay.
Report to Holodeck 2, Doctor.
You're all set.
The new parameters
will activate
as soon as you
enter the holodeck.
Thank you.
Break a leg.
So all I have to do
is find the controls
of this death ray
and deactivate it.
Well, it's not as
simple as it sounds.
Now, Chaotica might be
a 1930s villain,
but he's very clever.
It'd help if you
knew some of the rules.
I'm listening.
All right. Well...
first of all,
he's a megalomaniac,
so it's a good idea
to appeal to his ego.
Right.
And, um, use
grandiose language.
He likes to be
called "Sire,"
and it helps to
say things like
"The clever fiendishness
of your evil plan
is brilliant."
Deck 4.
Now, remember:
It's ray gun, not phaser,
um, imagizer,
not viewscreen,
Earthlings,
not Terrans.
Got it.
And another thing...
these villains always have
a trick up their sleeve--
trapdoors,
secret weapons...
It's the holodeck.
I can't be hurt
by weapons.
Well, that doesn't mean
that you can't be restrained
or thrown into
the Dungeon of Pain.
Noted.
Now, as soon as you get
the death ray shut down,
call me in my rocket ship
and give me
the signal to fire.
You'll have to use
Chaotica's broadcast
microphone.
This is how you've been
spending your free time?
Well, I've
been studying
how past generations
viewed the future.
And...?
Well, it didn't work out
quite as black-and-white
as they imagined.
Now, the specifications
for Arachnia's costume.
One more thing...
if you have trouble
with Chaotica
or you can't get
to the death ray,
you can always uncork
the pheromones.
I beg your pardon.
Uh, Chapter 16.
"Spell of the Spider."
Arachnia sends Chaotica a vial
of her irresistible potion.
Now, whenever he gets a whiff,
he's under her spell.
I get the picture.
Yeah, well, my point is,
is that these pheromones
seem to throw
Chaotica for a loop.
Well, it worked in
Chapter 16 anyway.
Now, the vial is sitting
on a small pedestal
next to the throne.
I'll keep an eye out.
Okay.
Thanks for the briefing.
I'll see you
at the Fortress of Doom.
And remember-- you're the queen.
Sire!
Three more
of our space ships
have been destroyed.
( growling )
Full power to
the death ray.
Citizens of the fifth dimension,
your feeble attacks
are nothing but pinpricks to me.
Surrender now
and I will be merciful.
We're receiving
a transmission.
They are surrendering.
No.
It's Queen Arachnia.
She wishes to cross
the drawbridge.
Ah...
What are you
waiting for?
Show her in.
I present
her Royal Highness...
Arachnia.
Ah...
At last...
At last... my queen.
This is an historic
occasion.
Kindred souls
meet at last.
It's an honor to be in
your presence, Majesty.
I've always
admired your...
clever fiendishness.
Ah, your taste is exceeded
only by your beauty.
This must be
your death ray.
That, my dear,
is the Cradle of Persuasion.
It's fully equipped--
a brain probe,
pain modulator.
Impressive.
It's good you have
the lightning shield
to protect your equipment.
Yes, as long as
it's electrified,
I am invincible!
But my greatest achievement
is there.
Behold-- the death ray.
Oh, it looks like a...
formidable weapon.
The most powerful
in the cosmos.
There is so much more
I want to show you.
My throne, for example.
The seat...
of my Empire.
Ah!
I see you've
kept my pheromones.
I didn't realize
you were the
sentimental type.
Your perfume
inspires me.
Would you mind?
Please.
Somehow I feel comfortable here.
Join me...
and you will have
your own chair--
one adorned with the
most precious jewels
and the softest silk.
Your Majesty seems
overly concerned
with romantic matters
when there's
a battle to be won.
That is why
you asked me here.
Of course, my dear.
Forgive me.
It's just that
the air itself
seems to vibrate
in your presence.
We can't be slaves
to our passion...
not when your Empire
is threatened.
I have assembled
my fleet of... Spider Ships.
However, the lightning shield
prevents them from
approaching your fortress.
We'll send them
directly into battle
alongside my
space force.
My soldiers wish
to pay homage to you.
Gratifying.
Of course, if
I lower the shield,
my fortress will
be defenseless.
Even an ally might
choose such a moment
to seize my throne.
You don't trust me.
There is a way you could
convince me of your loyalty.
Oh?
I'll lower my
lightning shield,
but first, you must
become my queen!
Gather my
courtiers!
Prepare for
the ceremony!
And don't forget to deactivate
the lightning shield
so my subjects may witness
the blessed event.
Very well.
Do as she says,
once her guests
have arrived.
Yes, Sire.
And so, my dear...
the day you have always
dreamed of has arrived...
the day you become
Bride of Chaotica!
( laughing )
( instrument beeping )
Welcome.
You are photonic.
Guilty as charged.
You signaled me
across the threshold.
How?
I believe you dropped
your calling card.
I return it to you...
as a sign of good faith.
Identify yourself.
I am the President of Earth.
Earth?
A planet
some distance from here.
I've come on a mission of peace.
Elaborate.
Your people
and the people of Earth
have a common enemy.
Chaotica.
The one and only.
He threatens
to invade our realm,
destroy our people.
Join the club.
Chaotica has designs
on Earth, too,
but we've withstood
countless attacks
all thanks to one man--
Captain Proton.
Captain Proton?
Defender of the Universe,
Scourge of Intergalactic Evil
and...
a competent medic to boot,
but don't say I said so.
Even as we speak,
he's preparing
to destroy Chaotica's death ray,
but he needs your help.
Explain.
Your weapons pose a threat
to Proton's rocket ship.
You must cease firing
while he mounts his attack.
Once Chaotica's death ray
is destroyed,
you can return to your realm,
confident that you'll never
hear from him again.
Captain Proton...
may proceed.
On behalf of
the citizens of Earth,
I thank you.
Space drive.
Check.
Destructo beam.
If I could access
holodeck controls,
the first thing I'd do
is delete this guy.
ROBOT:
Delete this guy.
As a matter of fact,
as soon as this is all over,
I think I'm going to delete
the whole program!
What about your
historical study?
Class dismissed.
No more robots,
no more mad scientists,
no more death rays.
I am retiring
my rocket pack, Harry.
Someone else can save
the universe from now on.
The final chapter, huh?
The end.
( door squeaks open )
Isn't anyone going to sing
"Hail to the Chief"?
KIM:
Mr. President,
how'd it go?
My performance
was unimpeachable.
He agreed?
Let's just say I'm considering
running for office
when we get back to Earth.
( chuckles )
All right, then. Let's get
this thing in the air
and hope Captain Janeway
is giving a command performance.
Queen Arachnia.
Don't tell me...
my wedding ring.
Doctor Chaotica's
wedding ring.
You will present it to him
at the end of the ceremony.
Your Majesty,
perhaps we should lower
the lightning shield
in anticipation of my guests.
Why this preoccupation
with the shield?
Oh, forgive me.
It's just that, as
a fellow ruler of the cosmos,
I often have
to do things myself.
Ah. Because of
the incompetence
of your inferiors,
no doubt.
Something like that.
Oh, Arachnia,
my love, my life...
how well you
understand our plight.
If it weren't beneath my
dignity, I... I would weep.
How I've longed for someone
who would understand.
We have a saying
on Arachnia:
"It's lonely at the top."
Hmm. No longer, my dear.
Majesty!
Proton is preparing
to attack.
Wha...?
Ah!
Target his rocket ship.
( grunts )
You have betrayed me.
You are in league with Proton.
Impetuous harlot!
Tell me how to deactivate
the lightning shield
or I'll show you just
how impetuous I can be.
What are you waiting
for, you great lummox?
Kill her!
Ha! You're no match
for Arachnia.
Now, tell me
how to shut down the shield.
The confinement rings!
( laughing )
Oh, don't worry.
I wouldn't kill my bride...
not until after
our wedding night.
Reactivate the death ray.
Destroy Proton!
We've been hit.
Well, I guess the Captain
ran into some trouble.
We're not going down
without a fight.
Doc, activate
the destructo beam.
The what?
The big button
in the middle of that panel.
Oh.
Destructo beam!
BOTH:
The other panel!
Destructo beam activated.
( explosion )
We just dropped out of range.
We're losing altitude.
Report.
The alien weapons fire
is increasing.
It's causing the distortions
to grow larger.
We're being pulled deeper
into subspace.
Invaders! Invaders!
Uh... incoming.
Proton's ship is damaged,
but still airborne.
Not for long.
Fire at will.
Lonzak.
Man the lightning shield.
( sniffing )
Arachnia?
Lonzak.
Quickly, Lonzak.
No time for dawdling.
Your beauty
is maddening.
Entangle me
in your web.
Let me out of here
and I'll do all that...
and more.
At once,
my queen.
( panting )
What...?
Back to your station!
( groans )
Idiot!
( groaning )
Deactivate the shield...
now!
Such passion.
Such strength.
Together, we could
conquer the universe.
End this madness
and you may yet live
to be my bride.
The shield.
( shield powering down )
I don't know how
to tell you this...
but the wedding's off.
Arachnia to Proton.
( feedback )
( groaning )
Arachnia to Proton.
Do you read me?
I'm reading you.
The lightning shield is down.
Acknowledged.
Harry, target the death ray.
Doc, fire the destructo beam
on my mark.
Ready?
Now!
( distorted screams )
The distortions are closing.
We're realigning
with normal space.
Helm... full impulse.
Bridge to Janeway.
Go ahead.
The aliens have retreated
and they've closed
the distortions.
We've cleared
the subspace layer.
Secure all systems
and organize
damage repair teams.
Understood.
We're preparing
to shut down the holodeck.
Chakotay, give me a minute.
( sighs )
I was about to say,
"Captain Proton to the rescue,"
but I see you have
everything under control.
I'm the queen, remember?
CHAOTICA:
Arachnia.
Death, as you know it,
has no hold on me.
My defeat
is but a temporary setback.
I shall return
to seek my revenge.
He doesn't give
up, does he?
They never do.
Our love was not
meant to be, my queen,
but be warned.
You have not seen the last of...
Chaotica.
The end of
a twisted madman.
And you're going
to miss him.
A little.
( '30s serial music playing )
( Chaotica laughing )