No! Make them stop!
Anything?
Nothing of relevance.
His neural pathways
are still fluctuating.
PARIS:
Doc...
Can't you do something?
Look how much
he's suffering.
If I sedate him,
we could lose any chance
of contacting the aliens.
Get them out!
Commander, can you hear me?
Focus on the sound
of my voice.
I can't understand them,
but they won't
stop talking!
What are they saying?
I don't know!
Make them stop! Please!
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Any progress, Doctor?
It's not
going well.
Our "Ambassador"
is still delusional.
JANEWAY:
We're running out of time.
The graviton shear
is buckling the hull.
If we don't find a way
out of chaotic space soon,
we're going to die here.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYS]
Chief Medical Officer's Log,
supplemental.
Despite my efforts,
Chakotay's condition
continues to deteriorate.
CHAKOTAY:
Doctor!
Yes, Commander?
I'm tired.
I want to sleep.
If you lose consciousness,
it could sever your link
with the aliens.
Aliens?
The ones who live
in this place.
We're trapped here.
They may know a way out.
It's urgent that
you speak with them.
But I don't understand
what they're saying.
I can try to help
you understand.
I'm going to end up
like my grandfather,
a crazy old man.
No. You're not crazy.
I believe the aliens
are reconfiguring
your neural pathways,
so they can
communicate with you.
Do you remember the day
you were injured
on the holodeck?
In the boxing
simulation?
Yes. You were knocked
down, remember?
I was injured.
I came to see you.
We had an argument.
That's right.
Try to remember more
about the holodeck.
I was sparring with
a Terrellian...
and Boothby was there.
He used to train me
when I was a cadet.
Keep going.
What round was it?
Three. Round Three.
The fight was going badly.
I was avoiding my opponent.
Stay away from the ropes, son.
That's it,
that's it.
COMPUTER:
End Round Three.
That wasn't so bad.
It was terrible.
Am I missing something?
He barely landed
a glove on me.
Mm-hmm.
Give him time.
You're not reading him.
You think he's
slow and stupid.
I know better.
In fact, I know his kind
in my bones. Literally.
I can count the fractures,
if you'd like.
He's not landing any punches.
That's the problem.
You're not letting him.
Have I got this sport all wrong?
Boxing is more
about taking the shots
than dishing them out.
You shouldn't be dancing
away from this fella.
Let him punch
himself out a little.
It all comes down
to the heart.
Do you have the
heart for this?
That's the contest,
it's not against him.
It's against your own natural
human desire not to get hurt.
That's the real fight.
COMPUTER:
Begin Round Four.
Go.
Go, go, go.
Stay with him.
Too close. Come on,
come on. Break it up.
That a boy.
Keep him busy.
[SLOWLY]:
Cover up!
[GRUNTING]
How many?
[EXHALES]
Three.
Good guess.
I've got a good mind to
use a needle and thread,
add a little authenticity
to your fun.
Be my guest.
You'd like that, a manly
scar above your eye.
"Chakotay,
the Maquis Mauler."
Pointless violence.
That program shouldn't
even be in our database.
There's nothing like
a good fight, Doctor.
I was there when Price Jones
went 23 rounds with Gul Tulet.
"The Knockout
in the Neutral Zone."
Best match I ever saw.
Really?
Most blood spilled?
Or did Price Jones
drive Gul Tulet's nasal
bone up into his brain?
[CHUCKLING]
You've got
the wrong idea.
The idea is
simple enough.
Do enough damage
to your opponent
to render him unconscious.
How's the headache?
It hurts.
Edema beneath the anterior fossa
of the cranium...
hairline fracture
of the septum...
I saw something strange.
I'll bet you did.
No, before I got hit.
What do you mean?
I looked over at Boothby...
He yelled at me...
I turned back...
Then the ring got distorted.
An hallucination.
You probably had some
pressure building up
along the optic nerves
from a previous blow.
No. I was keeping away
from him the whole fight.
He never touched me.
Hmm. A number
of the ganglia
in your visual cortex
are hyperactive.
Your opponent wasn't
firing on you
with an energy
weapon, was he?
Just his gloves.
JANEWAY:
Chakotay to the Bridge.
On my way.
I want you back in here
for some tests...
unless you want to be seeing
things on a regular basis.
[FRUSTRATED SIGH]
CHAKOTAY:
It's changed course again,
20,000 kilometers
off starboard.
Ion storm?
Not exactly.
It's two light-years across,
emits enough energy
for a dozen stars.
It doesn't match any
phenomenon in our database,
and it won't sit still.
Okay. Eleven thousand
kilometers
off the port bow.
We are too close.
I'm backing us off.
The phenomenon has been shifting
positions every few minutes.
Nothing so massive
could move that fast.
Full reverse.
Maximum shields.
Full stop.
Anybody want to tell me
where we are?
We appear to be
inside the disturbance.
I'm picking up
a lot of raw data,
subspace flux,
graviton waves.
Sensors must
be confused.
The readings are shifting
around so much, I can't make
heads or tails of
what's out there.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Captain, this is Seven of Nine.
Please report
to Astrometrics at once.
SEVEN OF NINE:
The Borg have been aware of this
phenomenon for many years.
It's a zone
where the laws of physics
are in a state of
flux, "chaotic space."
Why didn't sensors
warn us in time?
Chaotic space appears
randomly and unexpectedly.
The Borg have
observed it
throughout
the galaxy.
TUVOK:
Then why hasn't a
Federation starship
encountered
anything like this?
No doubt
some have.
Think of all
the Starfleet vessels
that disappeared under
mysterious circumstances.
Borg vessels
are more advanced,
but only one cube
has survived
an encounter
with chaotic space.
Those aren't
good odds.
If the physical
constants are shifting,
our sensors
can't function.
The problem is here.
Changes in the
gravitational coefficient
will cause sudden shear
forces against our hull.
Shields will protect us,
but only for a time.
How much time?
Unknown.
We've got to recalibrate
the sensors,
redesign them if necessary.
Otherwise,
we're flying blind.
Let's get to work.
[KEYBOARD BEEPING]
[BELL RINGS]
[COMPUTER QUIETLY]:
Begin Round One.
Computer, did you say something?
[COMPUTER NORMAL VOLUME]:
Negative.
[DISTANT CHEERS]
[CHEERING VOLUME INCREASES]
BOOTHBY:
Pick 'em up, son.
It's the fight
you've been waiting for.
[DISTANT BELL DINGS]
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
TUVOK:
Bridge to Commander Chakotay.
Go ahead, Tuvok.
Please report to the Bridge.
On my way.
Graviton wave displacement
says we're moving at Warp 6.
Subspace sensors show
we're standing
still.
We can't be that far
from where we entered.
Maybe we should
just set a course,
go to impulse and
see what happens.
What would most
likely happen
is a collision with an
asteroid field or a star.
PARIS:
That'd be better than just
sitting here waiting--
Report.
KIM:
Torsional shear
has increased
by 200 percent.
Shields?
TUVOK: Holding.
Like I was saying,
better than just
sitting here waiting
for our hull
to breach.
TUVOK:
Perhaps we
could drop
a series of beacons
to help us navigate.
PARIS:
Now that's an idea.
[FAINT BELL DINGS]
Did you hear something?
I heard nothing unusual.
PARIS:
I didn't hear
anything.
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
PARIS:
I'll plot a course
and we'll take it slow.
What do you think,
Chakotay?
ANNOUNCER:
The challenger...Chakotay!
Don't you hear that?
Hear what?
[CROWD CHEERING FAINTLY]
Look.
KIM:
Commander?
Are you all right?
BOOTHBY:
Put on the gloves, son.
I'm not ready.
Commander.
ANNOUNCER:
In this corner,
wearing the red trunks...
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
We've got a medical emergency.
[GRUNTING]
[DOCTOR SINGS NOTE]
[SINGS HIGHER NOTE]
Mm-hmm.
Let's go to 880 hertz.
[SINGS HIGHER NOTE]
Music lessons?
CHAKOTAY:
Pretty soon we'll
be singing duets.
DOCTOR:
I'm checking to see if
there's been any damage
to the auditory nerves,
nothing so far.
His vision checks out as well.
I'm afraid the source of the
trouble...
may be a little...deeper.
CHAKOTAY:
The family curse.
JANEWAY:
What do you mean?
Chakotay has
the genetic marker
for a cognitive disorder,
Sensory Tremens.
The primary symptoms are visual
and auditory hallucinations.
CHAKOTAY:
My family doctor
suppressed the gene
before I was even born,
so I never had to go through
what the others did,
like my grandfather.
DOCTOR:
For some reason, the
gene's been switched on.
I'm not saying for certain
that's why Chakotay thought
he was getting ready
for a prizefight,
but it's a good bet,
the holodeck boxing
simulation was fresh
in his memory.
A few misfiring
neurons did the rest.
This chaotic space
we've entered,
could it be stimulating
the gene?
Possibly. The only way
to make certain
would be to get the
ship out of here.
In the meantime,
the Commander will have
to stay in Sick Bay.
Tuvok tells me
you've got a mean left jab.
[CHUCKLING]
Never spar with a Vulcan.
How are you doing?
[SIGHS]
I'm all right.
When I was a boy...
my grandfather
started seeing things
nobody else could see...
hearing what
nobody else could hear.
He refused treatment.
A couple of hyposprays a day,
that's all he would have needed.
But he was stubborn.
He said
his spirit was in pain...
but that the wound...
must be honored.
[CHUCKLES]
Crazy old man.
Ready, Captain.
Janeway to Seven.
Bring the grid back online.
SEVEN OF NINE:
Stand by.
KIM:
We've got sensors.
I'm scanning
to 100,000 kilometers...
700,000.
Sensors are stable to
one million kilometers.
We won't be able
to scan any further.
JANEWAY:
Are you picking up
anything
at that range?
No planets, no asteroid fields,
no sinkholes.
Good enough for me.
Set a course dead ahead
one-quarter impulse.
Sensor status?
TUVOK: Still functioning.
KIM:
Still nothing ahead.
Good. Let's increase our speed.
Mr. Paris, go to half impulse.
KIM:
Wait.
It's a ship.
Warp capable.
It's adrift,
and the outer hull is damaged.
No life signs.
Let's take a closer look.
JANEWAY:
Computer, let's
hear that again.
MALE:
Why won't you answer?
Did you give up on me...
for being so late?
MALE 2:
Not my fault.
We got lost in here.
Why do the stars
make such a noise?
MAN 2:
Let me sleep.
I don't understand them.
I don't want to talk to them.
I just want to go home.
TUVOK:
That was the final
distress call.
According to the
vessel's medical records,
the Captain and one
of his engineers
started hallucinating
after they entered
this space.
The physician on board
never found a way
to treat them.
How long were
they stranded here?
Almost a year.
Eventually, their systems
were compromised.
They died
of exposure.
KIM:
The sensors on that ship
are more advanced than ours,
and they couldn't
find a way out.
Let's hold our position
till we have a better idea
of what we're up against.
It looks like that's
what they did.
And along the way,
a couple of them
started sounding
just like Chakotay.
I can't believe
that's a coincidence.
Then why hasn't anyone
else been affected?
DOCTOR:
That's a question
I can't answer.
Not yet.
Request permission to beam
their Captain's body on board.
I'd like to perform
an autopsy.
Granted. Pull the sensor
technology off that ship.
Use it to enhance ours.
We're going to need
all the help we can get.
I made a deep scan
of the alien's brain tissue
and sensory organs.
The optic
and auditory neurons
have been
partially stripped
of their normal
protein insulation.
The result,
auditory and visual
hallucinations.
The same symptoms as Chakotay
but a different cause.
Exactly. In this case,
the gene responsible
for producing
protein insulation
was shut down.
By what?
There might be something
in chaotic space
that reacts with DNA,
alters it.
But why it targeted him
specifically and now you,
I can't say.
Is there a treatment?
I can control the
hallucinations using
a neural suppressant,
but, unless I can find
a way to deactivate
that gene of yours...
I need to go on a
vision quest. Captain?
That's not the best
idea right now.
A vision quest
taps directly
into your
frontal cortex.
It could agitate
your mind.
Or help me control it.
Permission granted.
Very well.
I will ask you to wear
a cortical monitor.
It will help me keep
track of your vital signs.
Ah-koo-chee-moya.
I am far from the sacred places
of my grandfathers.
I am far from the bones
of my people...
but perhaps there is a powerful
being who will embrace me...
and give me the answers I seek.
Grandfather, what
are you doing here?
I, uh...
seem to be...lost.
Just a little lost.
You didn't take your
medicine this morning.
Which medicine are
you talking about?
There are
many medicines.
The one the
hospital gave us.
Oh, that one.
CHAKOTAY:
Where are you going?
My spirit doesn't
want that medicine.
I don't care what
your spirit wants.
You're going to take it.
I don't think so.
Come with me
back to the house.
Now why would
I want to do that?
It's better where I'm going.
It's more interesting.
Where are you going?
To the place
where my spirit lives.
Grandfather!
Where are you?
Answer me!
[BELL DINGS]
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
[CROWD CHEERING FAINTLY]
[CROWD CHEERING NORMAL VOULUME]
[BELL DINGS]
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
The aliens.
They were there,
watching me.
Inside your
vision quest?
They were trying
to tell me something.
What was it?
I don't know.
Are they with you now?
Can you hear them?
Yes.
Let them speak to you.
No! They'll make
me go crazy.
You're not going crazy.
They're doing this
for a reason.
You've got to trust them.
Stop fighting.
Open your mind.
Let go.
Listen.
Chaotic space...
intersects ours...
at the...18th...
dimensional gradient.
Voyager...
entered through...
[FAINT CROWD NOISE]
a trimetric fracture.
Trimetric fracture?
We must escape, or
we'll be destroyed.
How do we escape?
We've got to alter
our warp field.
In what way?
Rentrillic trajectory.
Rentrillic?
It doesn't make any sense.
I can't understand it.
I'm scared I'm losing my mind!
Try to focus.
It's too much!
I can't! It's too much!
Chakotay!
Get them out!
First contact?
It was brief, but he definitely
communicated with them.
Rentrillic trajectory.
Unfortunately,
they never got around
to explaining
what that meant.
Could be some sort
of alien geometry,
but we'll need much more.
Is it safe for him
to try to make
contact again?
Medically speaking, yes.
The problem is convincing
the Commander of that.
I realize
you're frightened...
but you're our only hope
out of this place.
You think this
could risk your sanity.
But your sanity
won't do you any good
if we remain
in chaotic space.
I need you to keep
trying, Chakotay.
Will you keep trying?
Keep me posted.
Are you ready to continue?
Try to focus on
the alien voices.
Tell me what they're saying.
I can't hear them.
Are you sure?
Listen carefully.
Maybe we can return you
to a more receptive
frame of mind.
Think back to when
you first heard them
in the vision quest.
What were you doing?
Where were you?
In a boxing ring.
A strange ring.
Was anyone else there?
Yes.
My opponent...
Kid Chaos.
Describe him.
Tuvok...
move into position.
TUVOK:
Thompson and Sharr,
target the midsection.
Ensign MacAlister, you and
I will aim for the head.
Set your phasers to kill.
Not exactly
the Marquis of Queensberry
rules now, is it?
"Set to kill"? That's not even
Starfleet.
Put down the weapons, son.
TUVOK:
Tactical advice from
an Academy groundskeeper?
We fire at your command, Sir.
BOOTHBY:
Give that order,
and you'll be out for the
count, the whole lot of you.
Lower your weapons.
TUVOK: Commander...
I said stand down!
PARIS:
We just heard from Vegas,
Mars and Orion III.
The odds are running 33:1
that he'll outpoint you.
Eleven to one that you'll
be K-Oed by the fifth.
Subspace radio
is calling it,
"The Disaster
in the Delta."
We can still
scratch the card.
I'll call the Doctor.
We'll get you out
on a medical.
BOOTHBY:
He's trying to
hornswoggle us.
Double check those calculations.
Let me see that pad.
Nope. Fine.
Don't want to trust your
friends? You're on your own.
[CROWD SHOUTING, CHEERING]
[GRUNTING]
NEELIX:
I'm filing a grievance
with the Delta Quadrant
Boxing Commission!
This bout came
out of nowhere!
There's some sort of
scheduling mix-up.
You haven't had
the time to train.
You're not ready!
If you fight now,
you'll be destroyed!
I can't fight now.
I'm not ready for this.
NEELIX:
Come on!
I can't stay here!
KIM:
I follow your example,
learn from you,
look up to you.
I don't want to lose that.
You'll find another role model.
You'll be okay.
JANEWAY:
You're my First Officer.
Your duty is to this crew.
If something
happens to me,
you've got to get
Voyager home.
Tuvok can take command.
TORRES:
You're being selfish, Chakotay.
I'm doing this for you...
for all of you!
A delusion,
dementia puglistica.
You're punch-drunk, Commander.
A hard shot to
the head and neck,
collapses the
carotid artery,
and cuts the flow of
blood to the brain.
The hook! The head and neck
twist laterally,
traumatizing
the cerebral tissue.
And who can forget
the upper cut?
The head snaps back,
rupturing tissue
in the cerebellum
and upper spinal cord!
Yes!
[SIGHS]
And the result...
of all this poetry in motion?
Neurologic dysfunction,
chronic traumatic
encephalopathy,
loss of balance
and coordination,
loss of memory.
Starting to
sound...familiar?
NEELIX:
Chakotay's fine.
He just needs a little
conditioning, that's all.
He needs to listen
to his doctor,
and not to
his fantasies.
Step into that arena,
and you'll become
what you most fear.
What are you talking about?
Oh, he knows
what I mean.
Don't you, Chakotay?
Hmm?
What's wrong?
Victory...
defeat, knockout,
TKO...
it's all beside
the point.
We know how
it really ends,
"a crazy old man..."
Hmm?
It's your fate,
your destiny.
There's no escape.
NEELIX:
You've just got
to do your best.
You can't let yourself
give in to your fears.
CHAKOTAY:
I'm not afraid!
NEELIX:
Who said you were?
[PANTING]
CHAKOTAY:
I'm sorry!
Please come back.
GRANDFATHER:
They got away.
Grandfather.
Where did you go?
Some people were
shouting at me.
They were going for a walk,
and they wanted me
to come along.
Oh...
It's hard to follow them.
Oh, God, they go
to strange places.
I'm supposed to
be watching you.
We're going to
get in trouble
if we don't go
back home.
Be a good boy and go.
We understand.
You have to
come with me.
They say you
can come with us.
There's nobody
else here.
They say you're
just like we are.
I'm not!
I'm not like you.
It's not so bad.
When you get used to it,
they're not so bad.
They're just a lot of talk.
Sometimes I wish
they were more quiet.
But they like to talk.
Come home.
No.
I'm too tired.
This is a nice place...
a nice place to call home.
Hmm.
[BELL DINGS FAINTLY]
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
Did you hear that?
No.
Yes, you did.
There's a lot of
them this time.
Tell them to go away!
Go away!
They've got other ideas.
[CROWD CLAMORING]
I have to go home!
Wait. They're
coming for you.
ANNOUNCER:
The challenger, Chakotay!
BOOTHBY:
Better late
than never.
They almost
scrubbed the bout.
I'm afraid.
I know you are.
You'd be a liar if you
said anything else.
But I've always
been afraid.
I know that too.
ANNOUNCER:
The champion, Kid Chaos!
[CROWD CHEERING]
That's it!
All over!
The fight's been canceled
on medical grounds!
[CHUCKLING]
Put 'em down. Let's go.
I hear there's some bearbaiting
at the arena next door!
Have fun!
[HYPOSPRAY WHOOSHES]
He's coming out of it.
You stopped the fight.
You were stuck
in the vision quest.
I've got to go back.
You're going nowhere
but Sick Bay.
Let me go.
Calm down.
It's over for you.
No, let me get in the ring!
Chakotay...
No. Let me back in the ring.
Let me...
Two hundred thousand
kilometers.
Launch another beacon.
Beacon launched.
KIM:
I'm reading a shift
of .003 in the
graviton shear.
JANEWAY:
Status?
TUVOK:
Shields holding.
Speed is steady at
one-quarter impulse.
JANEWAY:
Maintain course and
heading, Mr. Paris.
KIM:
Sensors are
functioning.
Our course
is still clear.
Captain, I recommend we go
to three-quarters impulse.
TUVOK:
Increasing power
to the engines
could affect
chaotic space.
There are too many unknowns.
At this speed, we should see
daylight in about two months.
The longer we're
in chaotic space, the longer
we're exposed
to these unknowns.
His logic is
undeniable, Captain.
We should increase our speed.
Finally.
Who am I to dispute logic?
Take a look at this.
It's the first
beacon we launched
three hours ago.
We've been going
in circles?
TUVOK:
To be precise,
one large circle.
Hold our position.
All stop.
Report.
I've applied
10,053 algorithms
to the energy signatures
produced by chaotic space.
There is a pattern.
Order to chaos?
Observe.
An isolinear frequency.
JANEWAY:
Some kind of signal?
I haven't located
the source.
It may be natural,
a star or quasar
that has managed to
survive in chaotic space.
But it could be
a transmission.
Possibly.
Have you tried
the standard language
decryptions?
All of them
with no success.
Success seems to be
in short supply lately.
Impossible.
Captain?
And to think...
that kept me
from getting an "A."
It was the only
question I missed
in exo-genetics
my senior year.
The nucleotide
resonance frequency.
That signal was designed
to activate DNA.
It realigned his
molecular bonds.
Now do you believe me?
They're the ones
who scheduled the fight.
They're promoting it.
They're putting
up the purse.
His sensory cortex
is hyperactive.
He's still
hallucinating.
It's not an hallucination,
not a vision quest,
it's a prizefight!
Chakotay, do you know me?
Do you know where you are?
I know you,
Captain,
but you stopped
the fight.
You ruined my career!
Nobody is going to put me
on the card after this!
It's better for you
to rest, Chakotay,
until we can figure out
why this is happening to you.
They want to contact me.
Who does?
The people who live here.
This will sedate him.
Wait a minute.
You believe somebody
lives here, in chaotic space?
And they're trying
to communicate with you?
Yes! I saw him!
Tell me about him.
What does he look like?
He's got a couple
of kilos on me,
a few centimeters
in height,
but I can take
him, Captain!
I just have to stay
off the ropes.
The holodeck boxing simulation
is still strong in his memory.
Obviously, it's the
primary source of imagery
for his hallucinations.
What if those
hallucinations
are being induced...
for a purpose?
Aliens who exist
on some perceptual wavelength
that our senses can't detect,
and the only way for them
to communicate
with us is
to alter our senses.
Chakotay's bad gene
gave them the opportunity.
What are you proposing?
Remember the derelict ship?
Two of their crew members
claimed they were seeing things.
Was somebody trying
to communicate with them?
to warn them, help them?
Or trying to destroy them,
just as they're trying
to destroy us.
Why go through
all the trouble?
We're trapped here anyway.
Let me back in the ring!
Even if this is
some kind of alien
communication,
it could harm him
permanently.
TUVOK:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Tuvok.
Graviton shear
has increased again.
Hull pressure is rising.
I'm on my way.
Captain...
when have we ever turned away
from a first contact?
Send him back in the ring.
Report!
Some kind of spatial sinkhole
just opened up beneath us!
Full thrusters!
Status?
We managed to
sidestep that one,
but graviton shear has increased
by another 310 percent.
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Sick Bay here.
JANEWAY: It's now or never.
Understood, Captain.
I've got to get in there.
They're about to ring the bell.
I'm going to subject
you to a field
that will enhance
the nucleotide bonds.
The gene should become
fully activated.
Do you understand?
I understand.
Find us a way
out of here.
I'll try.
[FAINT CROWD NOISES]
[BELL DINGING]
[BELL RINGING]
BOOTHBY:
Good idea.
Keep him waiting.
Let him sweat it out.
ANNOUNCER:
In this corner, representing
the Alpha Quadrant,
Earth and humanity,
the challenger, Chakotay!
Everybody loves an underdog.
ANNOUNCER:
And in this corner,
champion of the Delta Quadrant,
Kid Chaos!
[CHEERING]
Looks like he's got
a lot of upper-body
strength, a real puncher.
Just keep your elbow low
when you throw the right,
and don't come in too
straight, you'll be okay.
Where's the scouting report?
We don't know anything
about this guy.
I don't know who
I'm up against!
You're up against
yourself.
That's all
you've got to remember,
and don't raise the elbow.
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
Boothby, where are you?
BOOTHBY:
Still here, son.
I'm not going anywhere.
You...
Are...
Far from where...
You...call home.
You...Are...Lost.
Do you understand?
[GRUNTS]:
Yes.
We are far from home.
We are lost.
Our...
Home...
Is here.
[GRUNTING]
Our...Home...Is here...
In chaotic space.
Chaotic space...
BOOTHBY:
Hang in there, son.
Protect your head!
I understand!
We are too...
Alien...
For you.
We are too...
Strange...
For you.
Maybe we're the ones
who are too alien...
too strange.
If...
You...
Stay...
In chaotic space...
Chaotic space...
You'll be destroyed!
We know that...
but we can't navigate.
Our sensors don't work
in your space.
Twenty more seconds!
Don't go down!
Your...
Sensors must be...
Realigned...
How can I?
Your mind...
Must be...
Realigned... Realigned...
Realigned.
Your mind...
Must be...
Realigned.
I understand.
COMPUTER:
End Round One.
Get them out!
Let go, Commander!
I can't take
any more punches!
They aren't hitting you.
Duck...feint...
clinch!
Stop fighting!
I can't! They'll
destroy me!
That's a risk
you'll have to take.
You take the damn risk!
They want you.
Why?
Because you
have the gene.
The crazy gene.
Yes, the crazy gene.
The aliens are trying
to speak to you,
and the only thing keeping
you from understanding them,
is your own fear, your
fear of losing control,
your fear of
the unknown...
The unknown...and I
don't want to know.
But we have to know,
or we're all
going to die.
Allow yourself
to hear them
for just a few moments.
Do it for us.
What will happen to me...
when they're done?
You'll be on Voyager...
surrounded by friends.
I can't understand them.
You will.
They're talking too
fast, too many words.
Try to focus on one
word at a time.
Too many words.
Don't stop.
I'm scared.
Let them in.
I don't want to die!
They won't hurt you!
No one will hurt you!
[DISTANT CROWD NOISES]
Eighteenth gradient,
trimetric fracture.
Keep going.
We have to modify
our deflector.
We have to induce
a paralateral
rentrillic trajectory.
How do we do that?
I think I understand.
It's making sense.
Where are you going?
I can make the
adjustments myself.
I have to get to the Bridge.
I don't know how much longer
I can keep it in my mind!
TUVOK: Commander.
JANEWAY: What happened?
He's got a right uppercut
that almost knocked me out.
Move over, Harry.
Hang on, Ensign.
They showed me
how to get out of here.
He's hallucinating.
Out of the way!
Tell us what to do.
I can't!
It's too
difficult to explain.
I'm locking him out.
JANEWAY:
No. Give up your post.
TUVOK:
He's recalibrating
the deflector dish,
and routing it
through the sensor array.
It must be altered.
Captain, the graviton shear
is increasing.
I'm reading microfractures
on the hull.
Stay and we'll be destroyed.
Activate the deflector,
maximum amplitude.
Bring sensors online.
Captain...
Do it.
[KEYBOARD BEEPS]
I don't know how,
but the sensors have
found us a course.
Maximum impulse...now!
Captain, if the course is wrong,
we could breach our hull.
Engage.
We've reentered normal space.
[SIGHS]
Mr. Paris, resume a course
to the Alpha Quadrant.
PARIS:
Aye, Sir.
[FAINT CROWD NOISES]
[CROWD NOISE FADES]
JANEWAY:
When I said you should take
the next day or two off,
I thought you'd want to stay
in your quarters
with a good book.
CHAKOTAY:
Boxing helps me unwind.
Well, in that case,
report for duty
first thing
in the morning.
See you then.
Computer, run Chakotay
Training Program 15-Beta.
[COMPUTER BEEPS]
Ah, come for a little
more punishment?
Thought I'd spar
for a few rounds.
Uh-huh, after
that last bout?
Did you talk to the Doc?
I've got a clean
bill of health.
That's good
enough for me.
Okay.
I've been watching him fight.
He falls in too much
when he clinches,
and he moves
more to his right,
than he does to his left.
Well, I'll double up
on the left jabs,
and see what happens.
You sure you're
ready for this?
I'm ready.
Okay.
[BELL DINGS]
COMPUTER:
Begin Round One.
[THEME MUSIC PLAYS]