Hello?
I'm here.
( gasps )
( speaks alien language )
I'm here to see Mr. Kurros.
Could you...?
( speaking alien language )
Could you tell me where
to find Mr. Kurros? Ooh...
( beeping and clicking )
Wait.
( deep, reverberating moans )
Do not mind Bevvox.
He can be... grouchy
in the morning.
Welcome aboard.
Thank you.
You seem tense.
No.
This is a time
for celebration.
The geo-stability
of your world
has been restored...
your people saved...
and all because you
had the wisdom
to accept our help.
You accomplished in days
what our scientists failed
to achieve in decades.
That it not to say
it was not a challenge.
Finding the precise harmonic
for a planetary
containment field
did put my colleague here
to the test,
but, in the end...
she prevailed.
We owe you our lives.
Solving problems is what we do,
and seeing the look
of gratitude in your eyes
is almost reward enough.
Almost.
I have some bad news.
Our bernicium mines
were destroyed
in the last series of quakes.
The ore's buried
under 60 gigatons of rock.
We can't get to it.
We hoped you'd accept
this instead.
A rubidium geode.
Priceless.
The only one ever found
on our planet.
It is rare...
but hardly unique,
and it is not what
we agreed upon.
I'm sorry. This is all
we can offer you.
You are lying.
The mines collapsed,
but before they did,
you transferred the ore
to a shielded storage facility.
Needless to say...
we detected it.
Please, we need the ore
to repair our
replicator systems.
Without it, we'll be unable
to feed our people.
Get it to us now...
or I will deactivate
the containment field.
Have you ever experienced
a level-12 seismic event?
Most find it...
...quite unnerving.
No.
I'll have the ore
transported at once.
This... this was all
a misunderstanding.
Of course.
It is already forgotten,
my friend.
Perhaps we will do business
again someday.
Yes.
Show our friend back
to his shuttle.
I would hate for him to get lost
in such an unfamiliar place.
Oh!
Pardon me.
( door chimes )
Yes.
Captain, long-range scans
have detected...
One second.
I've wasted two hours
on this thing
and I'm no closer to solving it.
You can thank Ensign Paris
for introducing
the artifact
to the ship.
He was behind
the last shipwide craze too--
"Yo-yos."
Now it's "sheer lunacy."
Another hour and I'll go insane.
The solution is quite simple.
If you align...
No. I want
to figure this out myself.
You said something
about long-range scans?
They've revealed a planetoid
with high concentrations
of dilithium crystals.
Let's take a look.
KIM:
Got it!
False alarm.
Keep at it, Harry.
We're within visual range.
On screen.
TUVOK:
Initial scans revealed
substantial dilithium deposits
beneath the planetoid's crust.
Full sensor sweep.
( console beeping )
The deposits are in
the upper mantle,
about 60 kilometers down.
We'll have to use
phasers to cut through...
KIM: Hold on.
What is it?
Some kind of
resonance wave
emanating from the core.
It's building fast, Captain.
Right after we ran
our scans.
That can't be a coincidence.
Back us off, Tom.
The planetoid is destabilizing.
Shields.
Report.
We're trapped in a cloud
of metreon gas.
It's collapsed our warp field
and knocked
impulse engines off-line.
A heavily armed vessel
just dropped out of warp,
off the port bow.
SEVEN:
Captain,
I recognize it.
It's Hazari.
Species 4228.
Technologically advanced,
extremely violent.
They make excellent
tactical drones.
What do they want with us?
The Hazari are hired
to capture and deliver
alien vessels.
Bounty hunters.
Yes.
So who hired them?
CHAKOTAY: The Malon,
the Devore-- We've made
our share of enemies here.
They're hailing.
Surrender.
No one need be hurt.
My client would prefer
your vessel intact.
Who hired you?
That's not your concern.
I'm only asking because I'm
curious how much they're paying.
Maybe we can do better.
Doubtful.
We're far from defenseless.
Why don't you
save yourself some trouble.
It's no trouble.
Charge phaser banks
to full power.
Fire and you'll ignite
the gas cloud.
You'll be destroyed.
You've left me no choice.
I suggest you back off
if you want to save
your own ship.
End transmission.
They are moving closer.
They've locked on
a tractor beam.
Looks like they're
calling your bluff, Captain.
It was a bluff, wasn't it?
Seven, do we still
have warp power?
Yes, but it's useless while
we remain in the gas cloud.
Maybe not.
Reroute every spare gigawatt
to the shields.
Prepare
to fire phasers.
TUVOK:
Our target?
The gas cloud.
Do you believe the impact
will throw us clear?
If our shields hold.
That's a big if.
Go to warp 1 on my command.
Fire.
Shields are holding.
We're approaching
the perimeter
of the gas cloud.
PARIS:
We're out.
Warp speed.
No sign of pursuit.
They weren't
that heavily damaged.
Why aren't they following us?
There's the reason
they didn't come after us.
They've got
reinforcements
throughout
the sector.
Twenty-three ships.
And long-range scans
show more on the way.
Must be one hell
of a reward.
The size of the bounty
is immaterial.
According to Seven of Nine,
the Hazari pride themselves
on honoring
their agreements.
Great. Bounty hunters
with a work ethic.
CHAKOTAY:
There's got
to be a way out,
something
they haven't anticipated.
Download the data
for the Captain.
She wants to see what she
can come up with on her own.
Should I have the Doctor
prepare
a hypospray?
Excuse me?
So you can absorb
the caffeine
more directly.
Save time.
Point well taken.
I'll make this my last cup.
How about trying
a sounding board?
Oh, you don't want
that job.
Try me.
It's these Hazari.
They're like jackals.
Circling... feinting
to draw us out
while they cut off
every route of escape.
You make them sound
worse than the Borg.
At least the Borg
come straight at you.
The Hazari wait,
invite you to make mistakes.
They've anticipated
almost every move we can make,
and the few things
they seem to have missed,
I'm convinced are traps.
You still glad
you volunteered?
We've faced
tough odds before.
You'll get us through.
Good night.
Night.
There is nothing
like a good problem
to spark the
synapses, is there?
To open the mind
to new possibilities...
new ways of seeing things.
Of course, one must
always confront
self-doubt and fear,
but that is a
small price to pay
for the... exhilaration
of finding the perfect solution.
Who are you
and what do you want?
You have a problem, Captain.
I am the solution.
Security to the Mess Hall.
Intruder alert.
I deactivated your
communications device,
Captain, but do not worry.
I am not an intruder.
In fact, I am not really here.
A hologram.
Nothing so crude.
An isomorphic projection.
You actually enjoy this?
It's an acquired taste.
It bears a resemblance
to an Alkian confection
we acquired
several years ago.
"We"?
I am a member
of a small group--
Explorers like you, but
we seek out challenges,
problems to be solved--
Technological,
biological, social,
even artistic.
A think tank.
I like that.
It's very... apt.
Our "Think Tank" is nearby.
A modest vessel.
I have come to
offer our help
with your Hazari paradox.
"Paradox"?
That is right.
Is it an escape route
or is it a trap?
Do they know
that you know
that they know?
It is the best kind
of puzzle--
Pure tactics, psychology.
Something tells me
your help comes
with a price tag.
Whatever your culture has
to offer that is unique.
Technology perhaps,
or maybe something
you would not
even think to value.
I would need a closer look
at your database.
And how do I know you
aren't an Hazari trap?
Maybe they're trying
to lure us into an
ambush like before.
You are wise
to be suspicious, Captain.
We have done some
preliminary analysis
on their maneuvers.
It does suggest some
more likely ambushes.
I've downloaded the data
onto your computer.
All right.
You've got my attention,
but I want to meet
you face-to-face
and the rest of your crew.
Naturally. Our coordinates
are in here too,
but we have our own security
concerns, Captain.
Please bring only one crewman
and no scanning equipment.
Fair enough.
Then, I look forward
to meeting you... in person.
TUVOK:
We're approaching
the coordinates.
Full stop.
Looks like
there's nothing here.
Maybe they're cloaked.
I'm reading a subspace flux.
The vessel's hull is composed
of a neutronium-based alloy.
Starfleet's theorized
about such materials,
but we've never come close
to producing them.
Neither have the Borg.
The Think Tank's technology
is advanced.
Well, you and I will have a
chance to evaluate it firsthand.
Mr. Kim,
you have the transport
coordinates.
( speaking alien language )
The universal translator
must be inoperative.
Or his speech patterns
are too complex to process.
They must be studying it.
KURROS:
Actually,
she is studying you.
Our resident expert
on temporal physics.
Perhaps the most gifted
member of our group.
She finds you
interesting.
How do you
communicate?
One of my most gifted crewmen,
Seven of Nine.
Bionetic implants...
neural transceivers?
A Borg?
I've never seen one
outside the collective.
I am an individual now.
You may address
your comments to me.
Forgive me.
I am Kurros
and this is Fennim.
( speaking alien language )
In answer
to your earlier question,
this device allows the
members of our group
to communicate
telepathically.
Impressive.
( deep, reverberating moans )
It sounds as if another
member of our crew
is anxious to meet you.
A bioplasmic life-form.
His name is Bevvox.
He prefers
a variable-gravity environment.
What's his specialty?
At the moment, exo-sociology
and quantum mechanics,
but his interests vary
from time to time.
Bevvox founded our group
more than 100 years ago,
after wandering
the galaxy on his own
for a few millennia.
How old is
this creature?
( loud moaning )
If you please, that is
a sensitive topic with him.
And there is one
other... individual
who rounds out
our group.
( beeping and clicking )
An artificial intelligence.
The mind
of a mathematician
and the soul
of an artist.
I'm afraid he'd much rather
be modeling a fractal sculpture,
than analyzing the data
of our latest astronomical scan.
And now you have met us all.
A small group of minds,
but we have helped
hundreds of clients.
We turned the tide
in the war
between the Bara Plenum
and the Motali Empire,
reignited the Red Giants
of the Zai Cluster.
Just recently, we found
a cure for the Vidiian phage.
The Vidiians?
You would
hardly recognize them now.
Just last month, we helped
retrieve a Lyridian child's
runaway pet--
A subspace mesomorph,
I might add.
We had to invent
a whole new scanning technology
just to find it.
And what did you ask
for as compensation?
One of their transgalactic
star charts--
The best map of
the known galaxy ever created.
When we helped the citizens
of Rivos V resist the Borg,
all we asked for was the
recipe for their famous
zoth-nut soup.
Care for a taste?
Another time, perhaps.
Tell me,
is there any job you won't do?
What do you mean?
Well, we have a non-interference
protocol-- Our Prime Directive.
I'm curious
where you draw the line.
As you know, there is
no shortage of conflict
in what you call
the Delta Quadrant.
Many of our clients are at war.
To be frank, we will assist
in the neutralization
of fleets, starbases,
even planets, but we will
not participate
in the decimation
of an entire species,
nor will we design weapons
of mass destruction.
( artificial intelligence
beeping )
Hmm.
My colleague here wishes
to speak to Seven of Nine
about her bionetic technology.
May he interface
with you?
I am in direct
telepathic communication
with this... individual.
It is requesting
information about
integrating organic components
into its technology.
Feel free to give him
some pointers.
You're welcome.
To business, Captain.
I believe we can solve
the Hazari paradox
without firing
a single weapon.
That's just what
I'm looking for.
Then there is only
the matter of payment.
Voyager's schematics
and an overview
of its database.
Specify what you want
and I'll see what I can do.
I recommend
the replicators.
They're very
popular this year.
I'll contact you
with our requests.
I take it first
contact was a success?
I have some qualms
about their morality,
but I believe
they can help us.
It was an interesting
experience.
Glad to hear it.
We don't have much
good news of our own.
Every escape route
we've considered
is clearly a trap,
and more Hazari ships
keep joining the search.
Then we have no choice.
We'll put our own
plans on hold
and see what the Think
Tank comes up with.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You have a visitor.
Mr. Kurros has returned
in isomorphic form.
Send him in.
Welcome back.
Captain, we have
compiled a short list
of items we would like.
It was not easy.
Voyager has
a great deal to offer.
"Quantum slipstream technology."
I should warn you.
We never got that
to work reliably.
It is still intriguing,
theoretically.
"Neelix's recipe
for chadre'kab?"
Yes.
"An ancient Olmec figurine."
I guess Commander Chakotay
could be persuaded
to part with it.
I'm pleased
to hear that.
You can't be serious.
I realize the next item
may seem unorthodox,
but I believe
it can be beneficial
to both of us.
You never mentioned anything
about bartering my crew members.
She will have an
extraordinary opportunity
to explore the galaxy
as one of us.
I'm afraid the answer is no.
I understand
your feelings, Captain, but...
have you thought to ask
Seven of Nine herself?
A curious proposition.
To say the least.
How do you wish
to proceed?
I want your opinion.
They are offering us
the assistance we require.
I am the payment they require.
The solution is obvious.
This isn't a puzzle, Seven.
There's no "solution."
What's at issue here
is your future.
The issue is Voyager's survival.
Sit.
Please.
While I still question
this Think Tank's
way of doing things,
there is a genuine
opportunity for exploration.
It could be the chance
of a lifetime.
You're saying I should go?
I don't want you to go,
but it's not my right
to tell you what to do.
Until now, I've kept
a close eye on your progress,
helped you with decisions,
but I think you've learned
enough as an individual
to make this decision yourself.
Would you like to join them?
I am intrigued.
They are an unusual collective
with a compelling mission,
but I require more data.
That's why
I want you
to talk to Kurros yourself.
See if he can answer
your questions.
Captain...
I appreciate
your giving me this choice.
You've earned it.
And remember-- If
you do choose to go...
make sure it's what you want...
not what you think
is best for Voyager.
We're getting out of this--
With or without
the Think Tank's help.
Why me?
KURROS:
I admire
your humility.
The collective knowledge
of the Borg
contained within
a single mind.
When we factor in
your innate intelligence
and the enhancements
afforded you
by your bionetic implants,
we concluded you are
an ideal candidate...
the first we have
recruited in 17 years.
When did you arrive
at this assessment?
During your... interview.
My dialogue with
the artificial intelligence.
It was the most
efficient way
to evaluate your abilities.
I am sure
you can appreciate that.
How much do you know about me?
Enough to know
that you are tapping
into only a fraction
of your potential
as a member of Voyager's crew.
You were adjusting
the deflector array
to improve shield harmonics.
( chuckles )
Do you find such duties
challenging?
No.
Without problems
that test
the limits of your abilities,
you cannot expand them.
Perfection will always be
beyond your reach.
Seven of Nine, you could become
one of the greatest intellects
in the galaxy,
but that will not happen here
among these
limited life-forms.
The crew of Voyager
has accepted me...
integrated me
into their collective.
They are your family.
It was hard for me
to leave my family too...
and I was only a child...
not much older than you
when you were first assimilated.
Why did you leave?
To help them--
And my world--
Solve a cataclysmic problem.
The Think Tank
requested you as payment?
I did not realize it
at first--
I was too young--
But they gave me
a remarkable opportunity,
and now I am offering
the same to you.
Your group can assist
many collectives,
and yet you often
use that ability
as a means of coercion
to obtain what you want.
How many have suffered
because they were
unwilling to agree
to your conditions?
We have a singular mission--
To perfect our knowledge.
Perfection sometimes
necessitates selfishness.
It is your life...
not Voyager's,
not Captain Janeway's
or anyone else's.
It is up to you
to achieve the goals
you have set for yourself.
I agree.
But I can do that here.
Please, take more time
to think about this.
We will remain nearby
in case you change your mind.
I doubt that will happen.
TUVOK:
Seven of Nine,
report to the Bridge.
Acknowledged.
May I accompany you?
As you wish.
Do you have
a problem, Captain?
Two Hazari ships
are approaching.
I have declined their offer.
Our first offer.
Glad you're sticking around.
Take your station.
TUVOK:
They are dropping
out of warp,
flanking
our position.
JANEWAY:
Which one fired?
The ship to starboard.
Shields down to 60 percent.
Evasive maneuvers.
Target their weapon systems
and return fire.
Their shields are holding.
I can't get away.
They're right on top of us.
KIM:
Hull integrity's
been compromised
on Decks 7 and 12.
Captain, when the Hazari
strike in pairs,
one ship always
remains behind
to reinforce the shields
of the attacking vessel.
So we should target
the support ship.
How much is this tip
going to cost me?
This one is free.
I'll take it. Tuvok...
Retargeting.
Firing photon torpedoes.
TUVOK:
They are disengaging.
Get us out of here--
Maximum warp.
Thanks for the help.
Consider it a friendly
gesture of good will
in the hopes that Seven
will change her mind.
I have not.
You are making
a fatal mistake.
We have already analyzed
hundreds of scenarios.
Voyager will not survive
without our help.
Your scenarios,
not mine.
Your confidence
is unfounded, Captain.
Reconsider.
Order Seven of Nine to join us.
We have an old expression,
Kurros--
"Don't call us. We'll call you."
Remodulate the shields
to a phase-variant frequency.
TUVOK:
His ship is vanishing
from sensors.
It's being absorbed
into subspace.
I get the distinct feeling
they won't take no
for an answer.
Same here.
Looks like we're facing
two threats now--
The Hazari...
and our would-be saviors.
Our offer was denied.
How shall we proceed?
We are already proceeding.
Our offer was refused.
We must let
the scenario continue.
Our calculations
indicate
a 96 percent chance
the Borg will still be ours.
Then it is decided.
We will wait...
and let our problem...
solve itself.
MALE:
Duranium hull fragments,
a thruster assembly,
human organic residue...
We were supposed
to disable their ship,
not destroy it!
They've entered
the debris field.
Detonate the
spatial charges.
Their vessel has taken
heavy damage.
Shields and weapons
are off-line.
Move us into position.
Lock on a tractor beam
and pull them into
the shuttlebay.
We're in transporter range.
I've got a lock.
Two life-forms.
Energize.
Any luck?
I'm still trying to access
their primary database.
Let me guess.
They're the strong
but silent types.
Very silent.
Did you try
a mind-meld?
Without success.
They're unusually resistant.
Well, hold off
on the torture
till we see
what we can dig up here.
( beeping )
CHAKOTAY:
I found something.
A series of encoded
transmissions.
They've been
discussing Voyager--
Our coordinates,
our defenses.
Whoever hired the Hazari
know a lot about us.
Check their sensor logs.
See if they had
any visitors recently.
I've got some
bio-readings,
but they're
pretty scrambled.
If they are bio-readings,
perhaps the Doctor
can unscramble them.
Tell him to give it a try.
I've created
a forensic reconstruction
from the bio-readings,
using the holo-emitters.
Brace yourselves.
JANEWAY:
Malon.
Huh... they must
really hold a grudge.
We haven't run
into them for months.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
Something
doesn't feel right.
The Malon are
economically
motivated.
And there's no profit
in revenge.
Take a look at this.
Isomorphic signatures
embedded
in the bio-readings.
This was no Malon.
It was only
a projection.
You mean that's
a hologram...
of a hologram?
In a manner
of speaking.
I believe I can restore
the original
bio-signal parameters.
Brace yourself.
JANEWAY:
Well, it appears
our Hazari paradox
is more complex
than we thought.
I believe we're both being
manipulated by the same person.
Recognize him?
No.
His name is Kurros.
The Malon you met with
was nothing more
than a projection.
My sensors would have
detected a hologram.
Not this one.
Kurros is a member
of a... Think Tank.
They solve problems
for a price.
Oh, you have
heard of them.
They're notorious
in this sector.
They've made
quite a few enemies.
Enemies who might
be willing to pay
a hell of a bounty.
Their technology
is very advanced.
Makes them
difficult to track.
Not if we work together.
You're the best hunters
in the Quadrant
and we have the perfect lure.
All we have to do now is...
outthink the Think Tank.
We've got a puzzle,
and we're not leaving this room
until we solve it.
The Think Tank
is out there somewhere,
hiding in subspace.
How do we find them?
And even if we can,
their ship's hull
is neutronium-based alloy,
impervious to our weapons.
How do we capture them?
What if we send out
a multispatial probe?
It would take weeks
of scanning to find them.
HAZARI:
Weeks?
We're not willing
to wait that long.
We could use subspatial charges
to force them into the open.
Where do we target
the charges?
We've still got
to find them first.
JANEWAY:
Maybe we're
going about this
the wrong way.
A direct assault
seems unlikely to succeed.
"Pure tactics, psychology..."
that's how they solve problems.
That's what
we have to do.
They've created
this paradox
to manipulate us
into giving them Seven of Nine.
How do we manipulate them?
Think.
I thought we were onto something
with B'Elanna's plan to...
Forget it.
I was wrong.
Let him talk.
We're talking
in circles.
Enough!
Three hours, no progress.
I should have contacted
my ships by now.
Maybe we can't
outthink them.
Captain?
We have to assume
they've planned
for every contingency,
including anything we could come
up with to undermine their plan.
This thing
has been driving me crazy.
You said you knew
the solution. Prove it.
Seven, how'd
you do that?
I scanned the device.
Its mechanism operates
on a simple fractal regression.
You scanned it?
That's cheating.
Cheating is often
more efficient.
If you can't solve
a puzzle, cheat.
If you can't outthink
a Think Tank, don't try.
Are you suggesting
we give up?
Not at all.
When you were
in contact
with the artificial
intelligence,
you were linked
through their internal
communications array.
Yes, for several seconds.
If you were to link
with them again,
we might be able to
disrupt those systems.
If they can't
communicate,
they can't function
as a Think Tank.
They'd be
vulnerable.
Back to square one--
How do we find them?
Simple. We give them
what they want.
You're going to join
their group
willingly.
They won't believe her.
We'll have
to make them believe.
Pull up a chair.
We've got some
more work to do.
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE:
An Hazari vessel is sending
hails into subspace.
It's trying to contact us.
Put them through.
They're responding.
KURROS:
Hazari vessel,
we have received your hails.
Can we be of assistance?
You deceived us.
I do not believe we have met.
Stop the pretense.
You wanted us
to deliver Voyager.
Very well, but only
if you triple our bounty.
My friend, regardless
of the circumstances,
we have a contract.
Pay us, or we let Voyager go.
All right.
We will triple the bounty,
but you must deliver them
to us... now.
Agreed.
We'll contact
the rest of our ships.
We'll seize Voyager as planned.
TUVOK:
Shields down
to 30 percent.
Return fire.
Our phasers aren't penetrating
their shields.
That last volley took out
our shield generators
and phaser banks.
Life support's failing,
all decks.
KURROS:
Let us be honest, Captain.
Things do not seem
to be going your way.
Don't count us
out just yet.
I admit you have been clever.
You uncovered our subterfuge,
but you failed to factor in
all the variables.
The greed of the Hazari,
for example.
Photon torpedoes?
Aft launchers are still on line.
Target a full spread
at the lead Hazari ship.
KURROS:
A few torpedoes will
not alter the outcome.
If you do not convince
Seven of Nine to join us now,
the destruction of your ship
is 99.8 percent
certain.
Fire.
Direct hit.
It's been disabled.
Clinging to that .2 percentage?
Hazari reinforcements
should be here any minute.
PARIS:
He's right.
Sensors just picked up
a half dozen ships on an
intercept course.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain, I'm detecting
an unauthorized shuttle launch.
It's Seven of Nine.
What the hell is she doing?
I believe she's
saving your ship.
KIM:
She's not
answering hails.
Her shuttle's being
pulled into subspace.
She's gone.
Have a safe
journey home...
Captain.
Seven of Nine, welcome.
Your hospitality is irrelevant.
I am here because
you left me no choice.
You gave in to your
human instincts
to save your crew,
as we knew you would.
Just another factor
in our equation.
If Voyager is destroyed,
I will not cooperate.
Do not worry.
The solution to the Hazari
paradox is quite simple.
KURROS:
We have what we want.
Call off your attack.
Not until we've
been compensated.
Fine.
But first order your
other vessels to stand down.
Now, or we'll destroy Voyager.
Why is he in
such a hurry?
Comply.
If we de-cloak,
we would be vulnerable.
The Hazari could make
quite a bounty on us...
far more than
we are paying them.
Their technology
is inferior to yours.
They would never
attack you directly.
I think this is a trap--
A new paradox your Captain
has created for us.
If we call their bluff,
the Hazari might destroy Voyager
and we would lose you.
If we reveal ourselves,
we could be destroyed.
You told me,
"without problems
"to test the limits
of your ability,
you can never
expand them."
There is one
very simple way
to narrow the odds.
We simply link you
to our communications system,
allow our
artificial intelligence
to probe your mind
as it did before,
and Captain Janeway's plans
will be revealed like a jewel
in a bed of fog.
Sick Bay to Bridge.
Seven's neural transceiver
has been activated.
Acknowledged.
Do it.
I'm transmitting
the carrier wave.
( equipment powering down )
( beeping and clicking )
Voyager is sending
an interference signal
into our systems
using her cortical implants
as a relay.
Disconnect the link.
( speaking alien language )
They can't understand you.
Voyager to Hazari vessels.
Their systems are down.
Fire the spatial charges.
We seem to be experiencing
some turbulence.
Primitive spatial charges.
I will have the dome
back on line
before they can do any damage.
( alarm blaring )
We're being pulled
out of subspace.
I've got a lock on Seven.
JANEWAY:
Initiate transport.
TUVOK:
The Hazari vessels
are converging
on the Think Tank.
Tom.
Setting a course.
I urge you
to reconsider,
Captain.
A good guest knows when
he's outstayed his welcome.
We can still negotiate
a peaceful solution.
Do not destroy
my faith in diplomacy.
Your diplomacy could use
some polishing.
You know you will never be
satisfied here,
among these
people.
Is this what you really want?
Acquiring knowledge
is a worthy objective,
but its pursuit
has obviously not elevated you.
Looks like
your ship's having difficulties.
A minor problem.
Oh, I'm sure
you'll find a solution.
Just give it some... thought.