( imitating engine humming )
Alert! Alert!
Decompression on Platform 684!
Brace for hull rupture!
Thrusters are down!
We're going to crash!
( screaming )
Hey, what do you think?
Look at the detail
on that dorsal plating.
Impressive.
Are you sure you're
willing to part with it?
I just hope your boy enjoys it
as much as I do.
I'm certain
he will
if we make it home in
time for his birthday.
We'll make it.
If you and Sivad had
a child of your own,
you'd have an excuse to
play with toys more often.
I'm detecting a fluctuation
in tank 4.
There's a full-scale rupture
in progress!
Isolate the deck.
Activate the emergency
containment field.
The emergency systems
are off-line.
Backup controls
are down too.
Eject the tank.
Here?
There's
an inhabited system...
We have no choice.
The ejection ports
aren't responding.
Impossible.
( alarm wailing )
There's another rupture forming
in tank 6.
We'll have to
send somebody
down there
to seal off
the tanks manually.
Contact the Theta Corps.
Communications are down.
Get down to the injector pod
and seal those tanks.
I didn't sign up
for core labor.
I'm giving you an order.
I'll be contaminated.
Now!
The flame, like emotion,
is a primitive force.
Left unchecked,
it's chaotic, destructive,
but, if controlled,
it can be a powerful tool.
The lamp controls the flame,
as you must learn
to control your emotions.
I lost my temper--
No big deal.
You destroyed the Doctor's
holographic camera.
I told him three times
to leave Engineering,
but he kept buzzing around
snapping pictures
for some photo essay.
"A day in the life
of the warp core."
I apologized, and I
replicated him a new camera.
You have a long history
of emotional volatility.
The point of this exercise
is not to atone
for past transgressions,
but to prevent future ones.
You can't order
someone to meditate.
Commander Chakotay
thinks otherwise.
( sighs angrily )
Are my eyes supposed
to be open
or closed
for this part?
Whichever allows you
to focus your mind.
Envision the flame
burning within you.
( laughs )
Sorry.
The flame grows hotter...
a point of white light.
Follow it backward
through the years
to a time when you were
younger, a child.
( laughing )
Is there something
amusing, Lieutenant?
I'm sorry. An image just
flashed through my mind.
You as a child.
Those pointy little ears.
You must have been cute.
Indeed.
Please follow my instructions
or we'll discontinue
this exercise.
( clears throat )
Right. Me-- Childhood.
How old?
Your earliest memories.
Try to recall a time
when you experienced
uncontrollable anger.
Daniel Bird.
I beg your pardon?
Well, he was one
of my classmates
in grammar school.
He was always terrorizing me.
He used to point
at my cranial ridges
and tease me
about being half-Klingon.
He called me...
"Miss Turtlehead."
That angered you.
Of course, it did.
So I attacked him once,
during recess...
on the gyro-swing.
I disengaged
the centrifugal governor.
He was spinning so fast,
he almost flew apart.
Then I yanked him off the swing
and started pounding
his little face.
If Miss Malvin hadn't showed up,
I probably would have...
Describe the anger
you felt at that moment.
I...
I wanted to hurt him.
To take revenge for all
the humiliation he caused me.
Your anger was
a source of strength.
It protected you,
gave you courage.
I suppose it did.
And, when the Doctor
tried to take
a holo-photograph
of you?
I was annoyed.
He kept getting in the way.
The rage within you runs deep.
It's been with you
for many years.
I'm not a Vulcan.
I'll survive.
Whatever you say...
Miss Turtlehead.
What did you say?
You're easily provoked.
You must learn
to master your emotions.
I've had enough mastery
for one day.
School's out.
So how'd it go
with B'Elanna today?
Our meditation sessions
are confidential.
No. I'm not asking
for sordid details.
I just want to know
if you think
you can help her.
Her training will be
a challenge for both of us.
( chuckling )
Take it from me,
getting B'Elanna
to control her temper
is like convincing
a Ferengi to leave
his estate to charity.
( alarm bleeping )
KIM:
Captain, we're receiving
an automated
distress call.
Origin.
Coordinates
121 by 268.
Range: Two billion
kilometers.
Who's sending it?
I can't tell.
Let them know help's on the way.
Set a course, Mr. Paris.
37 escape pods.
PARIS:
They're
contaminated
with theta radiation.
Malon?
Possibly. Life signs?
Two, but they're erratic.
Beam them to Sick Bay.
Initiate biohazard
containment procedures.
TUVOK:
Theta radiation
has affected
a radius
of 600 million kilometers.
Source?
A Malon freighter traveling
at high impulse.
It appears to be abandoned.
TUVOK:
I thought we'd seen
the last of the Malon.
I guess they're looking
for new places
to dump their toxic waste.
Do we know what happened
to their ship?
Were they attacked?
I'm just as curious
as you are.
Can you revive
either of them?
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway.
Fesek...
( coughing )
Controller Fesek.
Where am I?
You're on my vessel.
We responded to
your distress call.
My ship...
It's heavily damaged.
Where?
Three million kilometers
from here.
That's too close.
We've got to get further away.
Calm down.
Tell me what's wrong
with your ship.
Why did you abandon it?
We were on a waste
export mission.
Dumping theta radiation.
Two of the theta tanks ruptured.
Systems malfunctioned
one-by-one--
Communications, navigation,
propulsion.
We had no choice.
Radiation was venting
from every port.
Over 60 crewmen died
within minutes.
It was chaos.
We stumbled through the gas
to get to the escape pods.
Only a few of us made it.
Where are the others?
The two of you were
the only ones
we found alive.
Listen to me... very carefully.
The fact that we're still here
means the ship
hasn't exploded... yet.
When it does, over four trillion
isotons of antimatter waste
is going to ignite.
Everything within three
light-years will be destroyed.
Janeway to the Bridge.
CHAKOTAY:
Go ahead.
Put at least five light-years
between us
and the Malon freighter,
quickly.
You heard her, Tom.
JANEWAY:
Send out a sector-wide alert.
Warn any other ships
in the vicinity
to evacuate immediately.
Our warp field
just collapsed.
All this theta radiation,
it's disrupting subspace.
Can you reinitialize the field?
Negative.
Tuvok...
Without warp drive,
there's no chance we'll
clear the blast radius.
Agreed.
Mr. Paris, set a course
for the freighter, full impulse.
Aye, Captain.
What?!
If we can't outrun your ship,
maybe we can disable it.
Every deck has been
contaminated.
Anyone who goes on board
will liquefy within minutes.
We'll find a way.
We? I'm not going
anywhere near that vessel.
You can either
stay and help us
or I'll send you back
to your escape pod.
Your choice.
Clean them up, Doctor.
I need them on the Bridge.
JANEWAY:
How long until those
storage tanks explode?
Approximately six hours.
Can we get
an away team on board?
The freighter's hull
is intact.
Life support appears
to be operational.
However, 33 of 42 decks
are flooded with high levels
of theta radiation.
Including the control room,
which is where we'd have to go
to reestablish containment.
As I told you...
We could beam onto one
of the lower levels
where there's
less radiation
and vent the contaminated
sections one by one.
Clear a path
to the control room.
I appreciate what
you're trying to do,
but if what you're
considering were possible,
we'd have tried it before
we abandoned the ship.
We have years
of experience
aboard freighters
of this gradient.
TORRES:
Your experience
is what got us into this
mess in the first place.
JANEWAY:
That's enough, Lieutenant.
Maybe there's another way.
I'm listening.
Four hours
from here,
there's a nebula
that could protect us
from the blast.
We could alter course--
Wait there
until after the explosion.
There are at least
three other ships
in the sector.
What about them?
I don't see what we can do.
So hundreds of people
become contaminated
because you're not willing
to clean up your garbage.
Lieutenant.
Assemble an away team.
We're going over there.
Wait!
Tell them about the vihaar.
What's he talking about?
Nothing. It's a myth.
CHAKOTAY:
What kind of myth?
It's an old story
shared among
freighter crews.
Some of them say
they've seen creatures
in the theta
storage tanks.
Creatures?
Created by
radiogenic wastes.
According to the legend,
they are poisonous monsters
that wreak havoc
aboard Malon ships.
It's a common belief
among our more
superstitious recruits.
I never believed it myself,
but during the evacuation,
some of the crew people
saw something, a form.
Hallucinations are one
of the first symptoms
of theta poisoning.
You know that.
Maybe. Then how do you
explain what happened?
We checked every system.
TORRES:
You'd say anything
to get out of going back
to that freighter.
If you'd been there...
you'd be afraid
to go back too.
This chamber seems to be
the least affected
by radiation.
We'll beam in there.
That's 15 decks
below the control room.
We'll have to
work our way up.
The pressurization systems,
they're off-line.
How will we vent the gas?
NEELIX:
There are two main
air locks on each deck.
We'll open them
as we go--
Perform a series
of controlled
decompressions.
What's to stop us
from being vented?
Force fields.
I spent six years
aboard a Talaxian
garbage scow.
I know a few things
about waste management.
Even low levels of theta
radiation can be lethal.
Our Doctor's developed
an inoculation.
It'll temporarily
prevent our cells
from absorbing the radiation.
How long will it last?
Two, three hours.
Half of the doors
and bulkheads are fused.
The ascenders are off-line.
It could take us
twice as long as that
to reach the control room.
Then we'll have to work quickly.
We'll take phasers
to cut through any obstacles.
I've ordered my men to do
a lot of risky things,
but nothing as
foolish as this.
More foolish
than towing around
a trillion isotons
of toxic waste?
We take every precaution
to keep it contained.
Until you dump it
in someone's backyard.
Is your crew always
so... diplomatic?
Your concerns are noted.
Get them inoculated.
We'll meet you in
Transporter Room 1.
We're trying to avoid
explosions, remember?
Oh, not another lecture
about my emotions.
No. A lecture
about how to treat guests
aboard this ship.
Guests? Chakotay,
these people
are the scourge
of the Quadrant.
Agreed. But right now,
they're our only hope
of repairing that freighter,
so I suggest
you make friends.
Diplomacy...
Janeway's answer
to everything.
This isn't the Captain talking.
It's me, and I'm
giving you an order.
Keep your temper in check.
Understood?
( quietly ):
Yeah.
I didn't hear you.
Yes.
B'Elanna, I need your expertise
on this mission,
not your bad mood.
I'll see what I can do.
( choking )
CHAKOTAY:
Ready, Neelix?
Uh, not quite.
Do we still
have a minute?
It's just... it's
not quite strong enough yet.
Oh...
Would you mind passing me
that little dish?
Neelix, I admire
your dedication,
but the crew can figure
out lunch on their own.
Lunch and dinner
and a midnight snack
have all been taken care of.
This is for me.
It's a Talaxian
theta radiation remedy--
Crushed Rama leaf
and Katyllian clove.
It helps fortify
the cellular membranes.
I think the Doctor's
inoculation might be
a better way to go.
Every little bit helps.
Oh, uh, by the way...
thank you.
For what?
For sending me on such
an important mission--
Not that my duties
in the Mess Hall
aren't challenging.
It was an easy choice.
You were the best man
for the job.
Well... our scow once ran
smack into a theta
radiation field...
knocked the propulsion out.
We had no choice
but to sit there.
We were barely alive
when they found us.
If it hadn't been for this,
nobody would have survived.
( grunting )
Once you get past the...
the choking reflex...
it's really not...
really not so bad.
Want to try some?
No. I'll take my chances.
KIM:
Transporter Room 1
to Commander Chakotay.
We're ready to proceed.
On our way.
B'Elanna...
aren't you
forgetting something?
I don't think so.
Well... uh, a "good-bye"
would be nice
"so long," "see you soon"--
Something along those lines.
I didn't want
to risk it.
Risk what?
Starting an argument.
Ha! Argument? Us?
So I hear it's been
a short fuse kind of day.
About this long.
Nothing you can't handle.
If you think so.
I know so.
I suppose it's always
going to be like this.
Like what?
Me against the galaxy.
Well, the galaxy
doesn't stand a chance.
Now... promise me
that you're going to be
careful over there.
No stopping to have fun.
Fun? On a Malon
freighter?
I'll see you soon.
( coughing )
Well, it's nothing
a fresh coat of paint
wouldn't brighten up.
This way.
Theta radiation
density--
20 million EV
per cubic meter.
Structural integrity
is holding.
( coughs )
I wish I could say the same
for my lungs.
What was that?
This corridor's filled
with methogenic particles,
highly charged.
( tricorder beeping loudly )
Something's causing
an electrostatic cascade.
Our scanning signals
are igniting the particles.
It's the tricorders.
Take cover!
( all coughing )
No more tricorders.
Control mechanisms are down.
We're going to have to open
the air locks manually.
Wait here.
We'll take care of it.
B'Elanna, go
with them.
We can do this ourselves.
I'd prefer to keep an
eye on your progress.
You're on my freighter.
I'm in charge here.
You abandoned ship, remember?
You take your orders from me.
We'll have to crawl
into an injector port.
It's only big enough
for two people.
Pelk, you
stay with us.
Shall we?
How can you stand
to work in these
conditions?
You think we're animals,
don't you?
You said it,
not me.
I'm a waste controller
half the year.
Do you know what I do
the rest of the time?
I'm a sculptor.
What's your point?
Every year,
I give up work I love
to expose myself to radiation
that will probably
cut my life in half.
Then why do it?
Have you ever been
to Malon Prime?
It's a remarkable place.
It's one of the most beautiful
worlds you'll ever see.
Our planet would choke
with industrial wastes
if it weren't for the sacrifices
of people like me.
How many worlds are you
willing to contaminate
to keep your own home so tidy?
Do you have any idea
of the trouble we go to
to locate isolated areas?
Manual actuators.
I'll release them.
You monitor
the pressure variance.
Right.
Do you have any children?
No.
I have a son.
He's 7 years old.
He wants to be
a waste controller
when he grows up.
You must be very proud.
Ready.
Torres to Chakotay.
Stand by
for the decompression sequence.
Acknowledged.
It didn't work.
There's something jamming
the air-lock controls.
Torres to Chakotay.
We've got a problem.
The actuators aren't working.
Somebody's going to have
to go up there and take a look.
Wait, that deck
is still contaminated.
I'll go.
I've been exposed
to worse.
Wait.
One for the road.
It's probably
just the decouplers.
They're always getting
encrusted with oxides.
( wheezing )
Who's there?
( clunk )
( wheezing growls )
( growl, blow lands )
( screaming )
( distant screaming )
I... I saw it...
I saw it...
What?
The creature.
Give me 20 cc's
of anesthezine.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Transporter status.
KIM ( staticky ):
Still too much interference.
I'll try compensating. Stand by
for further instructions.
TORRES: What happened?
We don't know.
He went away for a minute.
He screamed, and
we found him here.
These look like
chemical burns.
Without tricorders,
it's hard to make a diagnosis.
It's here.
What?
The creature.
You're hallucinating.
It's the radiation,
but you're going
to be all right.
No!
It attacked me.
It... a...
He's going into shock--
Cortical stimulator.
Pelk, get up!
( groaning )
He's not responding.
He said the creature
attacked him.
He imagined it.
He was probably scalded
when that conduit ruptured.
Or maybe there is someone else
on this ship.
KIM ( staticky ):
Voyager to away team.
Transporter interference
as cleared.
We're locked on
to your coordinates. Standby.
Harry... Pelk is dead.
Lock on to his signal
and beam him to Sick Bay.
Ask the Doctor
to determine
the cause of death.
Aye, sir.
Someone still needs
to get up there
and open the air locks.
Me.
CHAKOTAY:
Hold on.
I'll join you.
From now on,
nobody works alone.
Progress?
They've vented five decks--
Ten to go.
At this rate,
they'll reach the control room
in approximately three hours.
However, the storage tanks
will detonate in less than two.
I've been working on
a contingency plan.
An O-type star.
If the freighter exploded
within the star's corona,
it might absorb
the radiation.
The star is not
in the freighter's trajectory.
What if we gave it
a little nudge?
A series of carefully timed
tractor pulses
could alter
the freighter's course,
but, given the vessel's
weakened state,
one miscalculation
could set off the explosions.
I'm still counting on
the away team to succeed.
But I want to be ready with
Plan B if they don't.
TORRES:
I don't know about
the rest of you,
but I could sure use
a sonic shower.
NEELIX:
I'd love to soak
in a hot bath
for a day or two.
Oh, not me-- I want to
feel those sonic pulses
dissolving every last atom
of this grime off my body.
FESEK:
We have
a decontamination bay on board
that can purge
up to 50 workers at a time.
Well, that
sounds like fun.
( coughing )
B'Elanna?
I'm okay. I'm just
a little light-headed.
Your hand.
Oh, God...
FESEK:
Freighter blight--
From the prolonged
exposure.
Lovely.
In my business,
it's an occupational hazard.
We'd better try inoculating
you again.
If she's blistering,
she's already received
a fatal dose of radiation.
She needs treatment.
I'll live. Let's keep moving.
We have medicines
in the infirmary.
It's only two sections
from here.
We don't have time
for a detour.
B'Elanna, go with him.
We'll meet you outside
the control room.
Chakotay, I'm fine.
I said go.
This is the infirmary?
Looks more like a morgue.
What happened to him?
It looks like he
was being treated
for long-term exposure.
He was probably
left behind
during the evacuation.
Tough luck, huh?
There was nothing more
we could do for him.
He was a core laborer.
Meaning?
He worked close
to the storage tanks.
Only three of ten core laborers
survive a standard mission.
Occupational hazard?
They know the risks
when they accept the assignment.
They know they're going
to end up like this?
Core laborers can make more
in two months
than most Malon make
in a lifetime.
What good is the money if
they're not around to collect?
It will go to his family.
What is that thing?
It's a subdermal injector.
It contains analeptic compounds
to reverse the cell damage.
I feel better already.
I won't hurt you.
I've done this
a hundred times.
You'll feel a slight
burning sensation.
Commander...
the Captain's Plan B.
I've calculated
the inertial force
required to divert
the freighter.
Plan C: Shield modulations
that should reduce
the structural
damage of Voyager.
It will also help
protect the crew
against theta radiation
poisoning... if we fail.
A wise precaution.
With any luck, we
won't be needing it.
I didn't think
Vulcans believed in luck.
As a rule, we don't,
but serving with
Captain Janeway
has taught
me otherwise.
She does seem to succeed
more often than
random chance would allow.
I'll factor it
into my calculations.
Is there a Plan D?
No.
Initiating decompression
sequence, Deck 4!
Deck clear!
NEELIX:
12 Down! Three to go!
( alarm blaring )
The air locks are opening
on this deck!
What?
I can't close them!
Force fields!
Where are they?
They're off-line!
We've got to get
off this deck!
Move!
This way!
( explosion )
( grunts )
( all coughing )
Chakotay!
He was right
behind me.
Torres to Chakotay.
That deck is
a vacuum by now.
Torres to Voyager.
KIM: Acknowledged.
Lock on
to Chakotay's com signal
and beam him to Sick Bay.
We've got him.
He's okay.
I thought that deck
was secure!
It was.
Then why did we almost
get blown into space?
I don't know.
Air locks don't open
by themselves!
What are you saying?
You think it was me?
Calm down,
both of you!
We don't have time to argue
about what happened.
We've got to keep moving.
Chakotay?
Unconscious but stable.
The Doctor is
treating him now.
We'll be able to talk to
him in less than an hour.
I'll want a full report.
Shall I beam
to the freighter
and take command
of the away team?
I just spoke with B'Elanna.
She's got everything
under control.
This is a dangerous
situation.
There is no margin
for emotional error.
We have plenty to do here.
Help me remodulate
the tractor beam.
B'Elanna is unpredictable,
Captain.
Under these
circumstances,
her volatile nature could
compromise the mission.
Your concerns
are noted,
but, if I send
you over there,
I'd be sending
the wrong message--
That I don't have faith
in her, but I do.
Your faith is admirable,
but logic suggests...
This isn't about logic.
It's about trust.
She'll come through for us.
Now, give me a hand.
NEELIX:
Lieutenant?
Lieute...
Are you all right?
Fine.
Report.
We just vented the last deck.
We should have a clear path
to the control room.
Let's get this thing
over with then.
If you need to rest...
I said I'm fine.
I was...
meditating.
Meditating?
( chuckling )
You?
Do me a favor.
Don't tell Tuvok.
Your secret's safe.
It's this place.
I know how you feel.
The next time I
volunteer to board
a Malon freighter,
check me into Sick Bay
and have my
head examined.
I feel like
I'm ready to explode.
We'll get through
this together.
I got a knack
for diffusing
explosive situations.
Thanks.
Aw...
Torres to Astrometrics.
Go ahead.
We're outside the control room,
but without tricorders, we can't
tell if it's safe to go in.
( console beeping )
The room is too heavily
shielded.
Our sensors can't penetrate it.
You must stand by.
The theta dampening field
is still active.
It should be safe.
After you.
( coughing )
It's worse
than I expected.
Theta gas has leaked
into the warp manifold.
We've got less than ten minutes
before this vessel explodes!
Emergency systems are down.
This should feed enough energy
to your power matrix
to reinitialize them.
Try it now.
FESEK:
They're coming
back on line,
but only one containment grid
is still operational.
We have
two unstable tanks.
One grid
can't handle them both.
We'll seal them one at a time.
Doctor?
Easy, Commander.
Ow, my head aches.
I'm not surprised.
You took a severe blow.
I've got to get back
to the freighter.
Not in this condition.
If you want to help,
you can answer some questions
about Mr. Pelk's death.
I've found unidentified
tissue in his wounds.
What sort of tissue?
The computer is running
a microcellular scan.
Pelk said he was attacked.
Ah, yes, the Malon bogeyman.
COMPUTER:
Microcellular analysis
is complete.
Odd. The tissue is saturated
with theta radiation,
but it's not showing signs
of decay.
It came from someone...
or some thing...
that's developed
a resistance to the radiation.
Sick Bay to Seven of Nine.
Yes, Doctor.
Scan for additional life-forms
aboard the Malon vessel.
I've been running
continuous scans.
I assure you there is no one
there aside from the away team.
This life-form's
heavily irradiated.
It could be blending in
with ambient toxins.
I'll recalibrate our sensors.
Tank 1 stable.
Reroute the containment grid
to Tank 2.
What happened?
A power surge!
We're losing the grid.
It was triggered
from a workstation on this deck.
Janeway to away team.
We've detected an alien
life-form aboard the freighter.
We believe it killed Pelk.
TORRES:
Captain, we just lost power.
We're diverting the freighter
into a nearby star.
Leave the control room
so we can get a lock on you.
Acknowledged.
What's going on?
( grunting ):
It's jammed!
Seven of Nine
to away team.
I've detected
the alien life-form.
It's moving toward
your position.
The gas is being routed through
the environmental system!
I'll try to shut it down!
Is there another way out?
No.
( coughing )
Do you have them?
Not yet.
The life-form has entered
the control room.
( door opening )
( coughing )
TORRES:
I'm trying
to vent the gas,
but the release
valves are jammed.
FESEK:
Use the environmental
controls instead.
TORRES:
In the meantime,
see if you can get
that hatch open.
( grunts )
Neelix?
No, you'll ignite the gas.
( coughing )
Neelix?
We've got to get him back
to Voyager.
Get that hatch open!
I'm trying!
Fesek, behind you!
( growling )
( blow lands, yelling )
You're a core laborer.
Not anymore.
Stay back.
Don't make me kill you.
I'm already dead.
You've been
sabotaging this ship.
There's no other way
to make them understand.
So that's your way of getting
even-- Killing your crew?
Causing an explosion that
will contaminate other ships?
They poisoned me!
The freighter's on course
for the star.
Away team, we've adjusted
the vessel's course.
It's heading for
an O-type star.
You have to get
out of there now.
No.
No!
The freighter's maneuvering
thrusters just activated.
It's altering course.
Compensate.
No effect.
I'm detecting radiation surges
in the theta tanks.
They're going to detonate
in three minutes.
Harry?
As long as
they're in the control room,
I can't get a lock.
Janeway to away team.
Get those maneuvering
thruster off-line.
Then get
out of the contaminated area.
We can't get
a transporter lock on you.
Get the hell away
from there, now!
No!
It's too late!
Okay. Okay.
Look...
I know what they've
done to you.
They used you.
You want to
hurt them. Listen.
Listen to me.
I know...
I know that you're so angry,
you want to destroy everything
in sight, but there's
another way to make
them understand.
I'm on your side.
I can help you.
Innocent people are going to die
if you do this.
No. It's over.
Please. Please.
Please, let me help you.
No.
( grunting )
Step away!
The Malon's thrusters
are powering down.
I've restored
the freighter's trajectory.
B'Elanna, get
out of there.
Come on, we've got to go.
( grunting )
Fesek...
The away team, Mr. Kim.
I got them.
CHAKOTAY:
Maybe the
meditation's working.
What makes you say that?
From what
Neelix told me,
you kept your temper
in check over there.
Don't expect me
to make a habit of it.
Well, I've repaired
most of your
cellular degradation.
I wish I could say
the same for you,
but you've suffered
long-term systemic damage.
Your condition will
deteriorate over time.
It's an occupational hazard.
We've contacted
a Malon transport ship
in the next sector.
We've altered course
to rendezvous with them.
Thank you, Captain.
I don't know how I'm going
to explain what happened.
Tell them the truth.
Tell them
the vihaar is no myth.
( grunting )
( sighs )
Computer, activate sonic shower.