...so Harry throws it
in gear, floors the gas
and backs us right through
a burrito stand.
So when are you going
to teach me how to drive?
You sure
you're ready?
I've piloted starships.
I think I can
handle a car.
Ah, you'd be surprised.
The clutch on a '69 Mustang
can be pretty tricky.
Take a look.
She's watching
us again.
She's working. Relax.
Dessert?
What is it?
Some cheese I prepared
for our Kadi guest.
Tell me what you think.
It's a little bland.
Just a little?
Oh, that's bad.
The Kadi don't approve
of spices...
anything that might
inflame the senses.
You're talking this mission
very seriously.
The Kadi are easily offended.
The Captain's leaving
their representative
entirely in my hands
while she's at the colony.
I'm sure you're up
to it, Ambassador.
I hope so.
She's watching
us again.
You're imagining things.
I don't think so.
B'Elanna.
Enjoying the view?
Explain.
You've been staring
at us all night.
In fact,
you were following us yesterday
when we were walking
to Engineering,
and the day before,
when I was waiting for Tom
outside the Shuttle Bay.
You are correct.
I have been observing you
as part of my research
on human
mating behavior.
"Stardate 52647,
1400 hours.
"Subjects quarrel
in corridor
"outside female's quarters.
"Male returns with 12
flowering plant stems--
"species Rosa rubifolia--
"effecting a cessation
of hostilities.
"Stardate 52648
0300 hours.
Intimate relations resume..."
How the hell do you know when
we're having intimate relations?
There is no one on
Deck 9, Section 12
who doesn't know when you're
having intimate relations.
Is there a problem?
I want all the data
you've collected.
I haven't completed the study.
Then study this.
Borg provokes Klingon.
Klingon breaks Borg nose.
B'Elanna...
Call Sick Bay.
Tell them there's about
to be a medical emergency.
B'Elanna, let's go
have a nightcap.
This time, you've
crossed the line.
I've read B'Elanna's report.
Needless to say,
I was surprised.
I was careful not
to violate protocols.
That's not the point.
This is a starship,
not a nature preserve.
Oh, I'm missing a pip.
You asked me to broaden
my knowledge of human behavior.
I'm not questioning your goals,
Seven... Oh. It's your methods.
You shouldn't be taking
field notes on the crew.
Help me with this,
will you, please?
Have you ever considered
trying it yourself?
Romance, I mean.
I do not require
a romantic relationship.
So why did you collect
30,000 gigaquads
of data on the subject?
I'm late.
I missed this on my first pass
through their database.
Kadi monks only wash
with purified water,
so sonic showers
are out.
I've already
equipped his quarters
with an ablutionary fountain
built to their
specifications.
They observe eight
daily services.
Noted.
Show the ambassador
our best side, Neelix.
I don't want him going
back to his superiors
with tales of how
immoral we are.
TUVOK:
Energize.
The ritual greeting.
Travelers who have left
the sanctity
of their home and family,
we welcome you into our home...
our family.
Accept these symbols
of our purity
and the Goddess
Mother's blessing.
Commander Tuvok,
the senior officer
who will accompany me,
and Mr. Neelix, who will
familiarize your ambassador
with Voyager.
Tomin is an excellent
judge of character.
He'll help us determine
whether your crew is worthy
of receiving our minerals.
He's in very good hands.
It is time
to welcome you to our home.
This way, Ambassador.
Voyager's an Intrepid-class
starship
with a crew of 146,
designed for long-term
exploration.
I thought we'd start with
a tour of our primary systems.
First stop, Engineering.
I was hoping I might sample
a food item I noted earlier
in your data files.
"Hasperat"?
It's a Bajoran dish.
Very spicy.
I believe that your dietary
protocols prohibit
flavorful foods.
I want to broaden
my palate while I'm here
in the interests
of better understanding.
In that case,
first stop, Mess Hall.
Your cortical implants
are operating
at peak efficiency.
Nanoprobe levels
stable. Complaints?
None.
I heard about
the Mess Hall incident.
This crew can be
very efficient
at disseminating
information
when they choose to be.
They say gossip travels
faster than warp speed.
So why were you studying
Tom and B'Elanna?
Scientific curiosity.
Are you sure?
Perhaps there's a reason
that hasn't
occurred to you.
You're a woman, Seven.
Is that an observation
or a diagnosis?
A simple
biological fact...
with repercussions
that are hard to deny.
What is your
proposed treatment?
Perhaps you
should consider
expanding your research
to the realm of dating.
"Dating."
You mean procreation.
One step at a time.
Dating is a human ritual
wherein two people share
a social activity,
get to know each other.
In time, it can lead
to a romantic involvement
and eventually,
if all goes well, even marriage.
One step at a time.
This could be an important stage
in your social development.
It's worth exploring.
The Captain would
seem to agree.
How shall I proceed?
You mean, we.
I'll prepare a lesson plan.
Meet me on Holodeck 2
in one hour.
Most women start dating
a little younger than you,
but better late than never.
I've prepared
an introduction.
I call it
"Love Amid the Stars."
The Milky Way.
Home to thousands
of humanoid species
and countless
courtship rituals.
Klingon males
initiate courtship
by biting the female.
Here we see two Bolians
getting to know one another.
The courtship rituals
of some species
remain shrouded in mystery.
For example, Species 8472
appears to have as many
as five sexes.
Bystanders better
keep their distance.
( chuckles )
Of course, the species
you're most likely
to interact with is human,
so without further ado,
Lesson One, "First Contact."
There are any
number of ways
humans can meet
prospective mates.
Here we see
the "chance encounter."
Equally common is
the "formal introduction."
When first contact
is successful,
romance quickly ensues
and, in the happiest
of circumstances,
procreation.
Here we see how
fortress ovum
is besieged by countless
little warriors.
Doctor,
I am familiar
with the physiological processes
of sexuality.
Well...
then let's skip ahead
to the first
of the practical exercises.
Lesson Two.
"Encounter in a Public Place."
Computer,
initiate holo-program
Paris 3.
Our location?
Chez Sandrine.
It's on Earth in a city
called Marseilles.
Ensign Paris whiled
away a good portion
of his Academy
years here.
No doubt to the detriment
of his scholastic performance.
Now, pull up a bar stool
and pretend you've
come here to meet
the man of your dreams.
"Hi, there."
"Hello."
"Come here often?"
"This is my first time."
"You must be new in town.
How do you like
the south of France?"
"It is very quaint,
exactly as I've
always pictured it."
"May I buy you a drink?"
I don't require a liquid
supplement at this time.
You're not giving this
a fair chance.
This exercise
is pointless.
It may seem pointless,
but small talk is
a vital dating skill.
It helps to establish
a rapport with your companion.
Perhaps there's
something to be said
for assimilation
after all.
All right. Why don't you
try your own approach on...
that gentleman over there.
Go ahead.
Very well.
Hello.
May I buy
you a drink?
Uh... sure.
Steven Price.
And... and you are?
Seven of Nine,
Tertiary Adjunct of...
You may call me Seven.
Seven... that's-that's
an unusual name.
Uh, please, have a seat.
Looks like Sandrine's
is under new management.
Who deleted
my pool table?
Shh. School is in session.
More social lessons?
Watch. You might
learn something.
Curious jewelry.
It's a Borg implant. I was a
drone.
Oh, so then it's
a family heirloom.
( laughing )
Borg do not have families. They
have unimatrices.
Well, in that case,
why don't you tell me
about your... unimatrix.
They're hitting it off,
don't you think?
He's a hologram.
Your point?
Well, you programmed him
to interact with Seven.
Real people don't
respond the same way.
Under my guidance,
she'll be dating real people
in no time.
You're teaching
Seven how to date?
( laughing )
Talk about the blind
leading the blind.
I've had my share
of romantic encounters.
Hmm.
Are you implying
that Seven couldn't get a date?
What, are you kidding?
Half the men on this ship
would jump at the chance.
But getting a date
is one thing.
Keeping it from turning
into a disaster is another.
I have every confidence
in her social skills.
Well, fine. Let's say you get
her a date.
This is the holodeck.
The cards are stacked
in her favor.
But if you want to really
put her to the test,
you have to do it
in the real world,
where anything
can happen.
Mr. Neelix is hosting
a reception
for the Kadi Ambassador
on Thursday night.
Not only will Seven arrive
with a date,
she will have him eating
out of the palm of her hand.
Put your latinum
where your mouth is.
If Seven brings a date
to the reception
and leaves with the same date
on good terms
without causing
a diplomatic incident,
I will work double shifts
in Sick Bay for the next month.
And if she fails?
I get a month off.
It's a bet.
Where are you going?
Our small talk is terminated.
I have mastered
this exercise.
We can proceed
to the next.
If I were you,
I'd start looking for somebody
to fill in for me.
One Katarian pudding.
Mm-hmm.
Ah.
Mmm!
Ah, the texture
is so frothy.
It seems to be evaporating
in my mouth.
The recipe includes
a catalytic agent
designed to do
just that.
Mmm.
If we don't hurry,
we'll miss Lieutenant Torres.
She's been waiting
half an hour.
You're right.
Engineering.
Your warp core.
I must see that.
In our society,
males and females
work separately.
But I can see the wisdom
of your approach.
Promotes a more stimulating
environment.
( beeping )
It's time for third prayer.
Yes, it is.
But I think I can forego
this service
and perform
the appropriate penance later.
It's more important
that I continue exploring
your culture.
Perhaps another dessert.
Good morning.
It's time
for Lesson Three.
"Getting to Know You."
Elaborate.
The key to finding
a compatible partner
is learning how to share
your interests and goals.
We'll start with hobbies.
What do you do
with your spare time?
Regenerate.
Uh-huh.
Tell me about your tastes,
your likes and dislikes.
I dislike irrelevant
conversations.
Okay. Which brings
us to "goals."
What do you want
out of life?
Perfection.
Perfection is a laudable
goal for oneself,
but you can't expect
it from others.
I learned that
lesson myself
when I was
first activated.
One of the ways
I adapted was to pursue
interests people
could identify with.
Holo-photography,
for example. Opera.
Music does have intriguing
mathematical properties.
Excellent.
Perhaps we can mold this
curiosity into an interest.
Something you can
share with others.
Let's see how much you know.
Here we see--
A basic musical phrase
in the major mode.
I've done a preliminary study
of the topic.
Sing it for me.
( tone sounds )
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la. ♪
Seven, has anyone
ever told you
you have a beautiful voice? It's
a true gift.
The gift is
from the collective.
A vocal subprocessor
designed to facilitate
the sonic interface
with Borg transponders.
Let's try something
a little more challenging.
"You Are My Sunshine."
It's a simple melody
from Earth's 20th century.
A good piece
for beginners.
Sing.
( tone sounds )
♪ The other night, dear,
As I lay sleeping ♪
♪ I dreamed I held you
In my arms ♪
That was... flawless,
but try putting a little
more emotion into it.
Like this.
( tone sounds )
♪ When I awoke, dear,
I was mistaken ♪
♪ And I hung my head
And cried ♪
See? Computer,
add instrumental accompaniment.
( piano playing )
On to the chorus.
Together now.
♪ You are my sunshine
My only sunshine ♪
♪ You make me happy
When skies are gray ♪
♪ You'll never know, dear
How much I love you ♪
♪ Please don't take
My sunshine away ♪
( harmonizing ):
♪ You are my sunshine
My only sunshine ♪
♪ You make me happy
When skies are gray ♪
♪ You'll never know, dear ♪
♪ How much I love you ♪
♪ Please don't take
My sunshine away ♪
Seven, I need the data
from those last two
astrometric scans.
In a moment.
That looks like
the crew manifest.
The Doctor asked
me to pick
a suitable candidate.
For what?
Lesson Ten. "The First Date."
Your first date?
I've narrowed the list
to two crewmen
based on work performance
and compatible interests.
I didn't know you had
any interests.
Neither did I,
but, apparently, they include
astronomy, quantum mechanics
and music.
I play the clarinet,
you know.
You are not one of
the candidates, Ensign.
Oh.
Well, maybe I can help
you pick Mr. Right.
Ensign Bronowsky,
assigned to the Airponics Bay.
His work record is flawless
and he plays the accordion.
Badly, very badly.
He's got no sense of humor.
Lieutenant Chapman,
Structural Engineering.
Chapman's a nice guy.
We worked together
on an away mission.
He seemed efficient.
( door opens )
Robertson, if that's you,
I need an isolinear spanner.
SEVEN: It is not.
Ooh.
I apologize, Lieutenant.
I didn't mean to startle you.
No, my fault.
You need something?
Your presence is required...
...er, rather, it is
requested tonight.
1900 hours, Holodeck 2.
Another Engineering simulation?
Dinner.
"Dinner"?
The consumption
of nutritional biomatter.
No, I know what dinner is.
I just...
Are you asking me to join you?
Yes.
State your response.
Okay.
Yes.
Please be punctual.
I will. Thanks.
A dropped tool can be
a workplace hazard.
Be more careful
next time.
Seven, please state
the nature
of the medical
emergency.
I have a date.
( humming
"You Are My Sunshine" )
Sorry I'm late.
It's quite all right.
In fact, why don't you
take the day off...
relax?
Those double shifts
are going to take
a lot out of you.
Oh?
Seven of Nine has
a date tonight.
If all goes well,
as I'm sure it will,
he'll accompany her
to the reception tomorrow.
Who'd she pick?
Lieutenant William Chapman.
Ha! Chapman! Good luck.
What's that
supposed to mean?
He's renowned
for being nervous around women.
So?
Are you kidding?
Seven's dominant personality
will have him running
for the airlock before dessert.
Seven may seem
intimidating,
but that's only a reaction
to the way people treat her.
In fact, she's...
an efficient and
charming young woman.
Efficient,
I'll give you that.
But charming?
Most people don't
take the time to look
beyond her exterior.
Did you know she has
a lovely singing voice?
Uh, no, I didn't,
but then again,
I've never asked her
to sing for me.
What are you implying?
Well, it sounds like
you're getting
a little infatuated
with your star pupil.
( scoffing laugh )
"Infatuated"? That's absurd.
Whatever you say, maestro.
It was part of the lesson plan!
You're meeting with him
in ten minutes, Seven.
Why aren't you ready?
I am.
Aren't we forgetting
something?
Lesson Eight.
"Dress for Success."
My appearance is sufficient.
Sufficient, yes,
but you could use a
little more... panache.
Let's start by doing something
different with your hair.
I don't have much
first-hand experience
with this, but, uh...
Try...
shaking your head
a little bit.
Is this more appropriate?
Yes.
When I first designed your
dermaplastic garment,
I also tried my hand
at some casual attire.
You might want
to replicate one of these.
How shall I choose?
I think you'd look
very nice in...
this one.
I am uncertain how to
wear such a garment.
Assist me.
Oh, I-I-I'm sure
you'll manage.
I'll go prepare
the holodeck.
Remember, the idea is
to have fun tonight.
I'll expect a full report
in the morning.
( romantic piano music playing )
You-you look beautiful.
Thank you. You look...
beautiful as well.
Thank you.
( chuckles )
Uh, would you like to sit down?
Where is our
designated location?
Best table in the house.
I wasn't sure
you'd actually show up.
I requested your presence.
Well, to be honest,
I thought one of my friends
put you up to it.
( clears throat )
( sighs )
Um... champagne?
Synthehol impairs
my cortical function.
Water will suffice.
Mind if I...
Proceed.
I must admit I'm a little
nervous.
Elaborate.
Oh, um...
let's just say it's
been a long time
since I've been
out on a date.
I've never been
on a date.
As a result, I am experiencing
anxiety as well.
Well, I guess that means
we've got something in common.
( chuckling )
( sighs )
Uh...
Garçon?
( chuckles )
Server, report
to this station.
We require
your assistance.
( resumes playing )
Problem?
This creature has
an exoskeleton.
It's a lobster.
They're a delicacy
on Earth.
Try it.
( music resumes )
I will replicate you
a new garment.
I'm fine, fine.
It's just a little bit of...
exoskeleton.
( chuckling )
Maybe we should
order dessert.
You wish to accelerate
our social encounter?
No, no. I didn't say that. I'm
just, uh...
I'm having a very...
interesting evening.
( sighs )
W-would you like to dance?
That activity is
covered in Lesson 35.
I haven't
reached it yet.
( sighs )
Well, I'm not much of
a dancer myself...
but it might be fun.
As you wish.
( sighs )
Oh...
Relax.
Try to relax.
You seem a little tense.
Relaxation would disrupt
my chronographic sequencer.
It allows me to maintain
synchronous movement
with the music.
That's handy...
but maybe you could ignore
your chronographic sequencer
and, uh, let me lead.
That's better.
( snap )
Oh!
( music stops )
You are damaged.
( strained ): No...
I'll be all right.
You've torn a ligament.
I'm afraid you'll have
to report to Sick Bay.
Mr. Paris will treat you.
No need to mention
how this happened.
( groans )
I had a great time, Seven.
Let's do this again...
s-someday.
I have failed.
Nonsense.
Even Romeo and Juliet
hit a few snags at first.
Besides, Lieutenant Chapman's
not the only lobster in the sea.
I wish to terminate our social
lessons.
Just because you didn't
achieve perfection
your first time out doesn't mean
you should give up.
Dating is a poor means
of interaction.
There is
far more efficiency
in the way
you and I communicate.
We say what we mean
simply and directly.
You and I do
have a rapport,
but we're colleagues.
We're not
pursuing romance.
No.
I'm certain you'll be able
to master these basic
skills in short order.
My first date was
certainly short.
Was that a joke?
Lesson Six.
"Beguiling Banter."
Now you're getting
the hang of it.
Perhaps this evening doesn't
have to end so abruptly.
This may be a good time
to cover Lesson 35.
"Shall We Dance?"
Computer,
play "Someone To Watch Over Me"
instrumental only.
( piano intro playing )
We'll begin with
some simple steps.
Place your left hand
on my shoulder
and your right
hand in my left.
Now... follow me...
one step at a time.
Don't worry. I don't have
any ligaments to tear.
( laughing )
Another drink!
Ambassador!
Neelix!
( drunkenly ):
My friend,
my... host...
my... savior.
Neelix, I want you
to meet, uh...
Alandra...
( laughs heartily )
and Tria.
What are you doing?
I'm sampling yet another entrée
on the menu of pleasure
that you have opened up for me.
I checked today's menu,
and they're not on it.
Coffee, black.
Neelix, I decided
to go exploring
and I found your holodecks...
and I discovered
this little gem
still simmering
in the memory buffer.
We can explore it later.
Right now, we've got to get you
to your reception.
Mmm... pungent taste.
What is it?
Coffee
and there's plenty more
where we're going.
No coffee on
our colony.
Nothing to tempt
the appetite
of even the most
weak-willed novitiate.
Neelix, a confession.
I am thinking of
leaving the colony,
joining Voyager.
I want to throw
off my vows
and immerse myself in
your wonderful culture.
That's just
the synthehol talking.
No, I've never been more
clear-headed about anything.
And I have you to thank.
That's right...
there we go...
It's all you...
Hard at work?
Our lessons
have disrupted my duties.
Then I suppose
you're too busy
to attend the
Ambassador's reception.
My presence
is not required.
True, but it might be
an opportunity for you
to apply your newfound
social skills.
Lesson 11.
"Life of the Party."
Exactly. Join me?
Are you asking me
on a date?
I suppose I am.
Then I accept.
Is my appearance sufficient?
You look perfect.
( Tomin laughing )
PARIS:
How do you bend
a hologram's ear?
Use a prism.
What did the counselor
say to the hologram?
"You're projecting."
This humor...
it's a revelation.
Ambassador?
Very good.
Uh... are-are you sure
you wouldn't prefer
some more coffee, Ambassador?
Coffee. Mmm, yes.
I'll have that too.
Go.
Neelix...
is it my imagination
or is our guest
of honor drunk?
Commander, I tried.
I had an itinerary.
I even set up a prayer dais
in his quarters,
but I just
couldn't control him.
The Captain is due
back in the morning
with the Kadi Minister.
What do I do?
Pray.
Well, well, well. What do we
have here?
Mr. Paris, I believe you know
Seven of Nine,
my date for the evening.
Oh, you don't say?
Well, your last date
ended up in Sick Bay.
I hope this one
goes a little smoother.
There's no need
to be insulting.
It's all right, Doctor.
I believe he is merely
engaging in small talk.
May I get either
of you gentlemen a drink?
Ah, yes, gin and
tonic with a twist.
You know I don't drink.
I don't have the stomach for it.
A well-crafted joke,
Doctor.
Impressive. You've actually
taught her to be polite.
But don't think
you've won our bet.
She was supposed to
bring a real date.
Photons and force fields,
flesh and blood...
why quibble over details?
I'm just as real
as any of you.
TOMIN ( hollering ):
Where is that funny man?
Mr. Tomin, please,
why don't we sit down?
Ah, there he is--
There he is.
Ensign Paris, tell us
another one of those
hologram jokes.
You've been stealing
my material?
That guy's so lubricated
he'll laugh at anything.
There he is.
The Ambassador of Humor.
I could use a little help here.
Seven, perhaps now
would be a good time
to review Lesson 23.
"Toast of the Town."
Very well.
( tapping on glass )
Ladies and gentlemen,
I require your attention.
May cultural differences
encourage us
to build bridges
of understanding.
To all that makes us unique.
Who is that
extraordinary female?
Seven of Nine.
I want to meet her.
Take a number.
That was lovely.
Thank you.
I've got to admit it.
You've done wonders.
All right, you win.
"Win"?
I know when I'm licked.
You tell me when you want me
to start those double shifts.
You made a wager
regarding me? Clarify.
It's not what you think.
Um, don't blame him.
It was my idea.
I believed your interest
in my social
development was sincere,
not motivated by
personal gain.
It was sincere.
Clearly, I am
not the only one
who requires social lessons.
Thank you for a
lovely evening.
Hey...
Why don't we
go back to my quarters?
I've studied human
mating rituals.
Remove your hand
or I will remove your arm.
Did you hear
what she said to me?!
I am the guest of honor!
Ambassador,
it's been a long day.
Maybe you should
get some rest.
No! I'm not leaving!
I want another drink!
I thought synthehol
wasn't supposed
to have this effect
on people.
Most people. The enzymes
that break down synthehol
aren't present
in his bloodstream.
Can you counteract
the effects?
I can synthesize the enzymes,
but that'll take days.
Days? The Captain will
be back in the morning.
Maybe he needs a cold shower.
If his superiors
find him like this,
he'll be banished
from the colony
and our trade agreement
will go right out the airlock.
Oh, Seven of mine.
It may be possible to encode
some of my nanoprobes
to assimilate
the synthehol molecules.
Assimilate me.
There may be some
adverse effects.
Please...
But it's worth a try.
The Kadi have
rules against
medical procedures
that haven't been sanctified.
I'd say he's already
violated a few rules.
What's one more?
Either we treat him or
he remains intoxicated.
You're his caretaker.
Decide.
Nanoprobes.
I owe you an apology.
Nanoprobe extraction is an
insignificant procedure.
My systems will adapt.
No...
I'm referring to the...
wager I made with Ensign Paris.
I can see how you
might have felt manipulated,
but I assure you
that was never my intention.
I accept your apology.
I want to make this
perfectly clear,
so there's no room
for misunderstanding.
I asked you to go with me
to the reception
because I enjoy your company.
In fact,
over the last few days,
I feel as though we've...
grown closer.
Closer?
We've become
more than colleagues.
We're...
friends.
Friends? Agreed.
I should begin.
Of course.
I'll take over from here.
Mr. Paris...
hypothetically...
if one develops romantic
feelings for another person,
how does one usually
go about expressing them?
It's for one of Seven's
social lessons.
Ah... well, I recommend
the direct approach.
Tell the person how you feel.
What if the feelings
aren't mutual?
Well, that's the risk
you always take.
Oh... thank you.
Why don't you tell her?
Come on, Doc.
It's obvious the Ambassador
is not the only one
in this room who's intoxicated.
Impossible.
She's my student.
A hologram and a Borg?
Stranger things have happened.
Just look at me
and B'Elanna.
Uh, could... could we
walk a little slower?
They're due back
any minute.
But my throat feels like an
ancient parchment.
Can't we go
back to Sandrine's
for a refreshing glass of...
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No. No, no, no, no.
Those doors... they're so loud.
You've got a hangover.
Neelix, I don't remember
much of last night,
but... I imagine I might
have said some things...
You spoke eloquently... charmed
the entire crew...
your reception was a
success. Understand?
Yes.
Neelix, you've been
most patient.
Well, that's my job.
And it isn't over yet.
Welcome back!
JANEWAY: Good to be home.
How's it going?
All systems
functioning normally.
Ensign Kim detected
a minor fluctuation
in the sensor array,
but he took care of it.
I was referring
to Ambassador Tomin.
Did he enjoy his visit?
Oh, well...
well, I would say
that he, uh...
he enjoyed himself
immensely.
There are many distractions
aboard this vessel.
You didn't indulge
in any of their more...
colorful traditions?
Of course not!
We followed the itinerary
that you approved
to the last detail.
Oh... shame.
Your Holiness?
It isn't a violation
to explore new experiences...
as long as you don't make
a habit of it.
I see your point.
Shall we conclude
our negotiations, Captain?
By all means.
I'll show you to
the briefing room.
Good work... Ambassador.
DOCTOR:
Do you like them?
Species Rosa rubifolia.
State your intention.
I wanted to
congratulate you
on the latest phase of
your social development.
Why don't you
read the card?
"You are my sunshine."
These past few days
have been...
unforgettable.
You've brought light
into my life, Seven.
You have developed
romantic feelings for me.
It's as if you've become
a part of my program.
When we're apart, I feel like
I'm missing a subroutine.
I don't expect you
to reciprocate...
but I wanted you
to know how I feel.
( door chimes )
Computer, end program.
Enter.
Seven...
I wish to
speak with you.
What a coincidence.
I... was hoping to speak
with you as well.
Regarding?
You first.
What's this?
It's a medical tricorder.
I enhanced its scanning
resolution by 33 percent.
You once stated you desired
a more efficient instrument.
I suppose I did.
It is a gift.
Lesson 22.
"Thanks for the Memories."
Is it insufficient?
No... no.
It's very thoughtful.
I chose to convey my gratitude
at this time
because I no longer require
your assistance.
It's obvious
there are
no potential mates for me
aboard this vessel.
However, if I encounter
a compatible individual
in the future, I will again
seek your guidance.
Guidance.
Of course.
You said you had something
to tell me.
I just wanted to say...
the past few days...
have been unforgettable.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Computer, activate
holo-program Paris 3.
( slow piano introduction )
♪ Won't you tell her please
To put on some speed ♪
♪ Follow my lead ♪
♪ Oh, how I need ♪
♪ Someone to watch over me ♪