Good morning!
Morning.
Requisition reports
for the week.
Thanks.
What can you tell me
about the Great
Wall of China?
Pardon?
The Great Wall of China,
on Earth. Who built it?
The Chinese.
What for?
Why does anybody build a wall?
To keep people out.
Deck 1.
In fact, it was
the first Qin emperor
who connected the walls
built by a previous dynasty.
He did it to prevent an invasion
by nomads to the north.
How big is it?
I have a feeling
you're going to tell me.
2,400 kilometers long,
median width 3.8 meters.
Before the 22nd century,
it was one of the
only manmade objects
that could be seen
from Earth's orbit
with the naked eye.
Very impressive, Neelix.
I had no idea you knew so much
about my homeworld.
Status?
We're on a course
for the class-Y cluster.
We should be there
in about three days.
Gives us some time
to relax. Carry on.
Why this sudden interest
in the Great Wall?
I've been studying
Earth landmarks.
Mr. Paris and I
have been exchanging
a little cross-cultural
trivia.
He's become quite an expert
on Talaxian geography.
All right,
here's one for you.
What can you tell me
about the Millennium Gate?
The Millennium Gate--
Constructed in the 21st century
in the United States of America.
It was another
one of the objects
that could be seen from orbit.
Uh, 3.2 kilometers at the base.
One kilometer in height.
Surface covered with
highly reflective
solar panels.
A self-contained
ecosystem.
It became a model for
the first colony on Mars.
Did you know that one of
my ancestors built it?
Really?
Not with a hammer
and nails,
but with words and
a lot of courage.
Shannon O'Donnel, one of
the first woman astronauts--
She was the driving force
behind the project.
That's something
to be proud of.
We were always told stories
about her at family
gatherings--
"The first of a long line
of Janeway explorers."
Tell me more.
I want something
to stump Mr. Paris with.
Where to begin?
The Millennium Gate.
How did she get
involved with that?
Well, at that time, she was
still in the space program,
but she'd also become something
of an entrepreneur.
I believe she was asked
to join the project
by the Governor of Indiana.
He wanted her expertise on
recyclic life-support systems.
The way my Aunt Martha
tells it,
they flew her in
on a private aircraft.
5:00 am, December 27, 2000.
I'm in the great state
of... Indiana, I think.
I saw the world's largest ball
of string this morning
and the world's largest
beefsteak tomato this afternoon.
It was the size
of a Volkswagen--
The string, not the tomato.
At least Christmas is over.
( engine knocking )
( groaning ):
Oh, no...
Excuse me.
I think I made a wrong turn.
Is there a Millennium Gate
around here?
You're looking at it.
The sign said
"Gas, Food, Lodging."
I need all three.
You won't find
any of that here.
Get back on the interstate
and go to Exit Nine.
I don't think
I'm going to make it.
Good luck.
Tell me, are people a little
friendlier off Exit Nine?
( sighing ):
Oh, no.
You stopped.
You didn't.
You got a pen?
I... I just
didn't see you.
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
Insurance?
Not really.
"Not really"?
It ran out.
Oh, it's not too bad.
200 bucks ought
to cover it.
200 bucks?
Let me guess--
The money ran out too.
( sighs )
Hi.
The sign said "open"?
Yes, that's right.
Till 6:00.
Can we be of assistance?
It's cold outside, and I-I
wondered if I could wait here.
For what?
For the tow truck.
My car broke down.
I'm trying to get to Florida.
She doesn't look like
a corporate hit man.
I assure you I'm not...
at least not anymore.
Well, in any case, she's unarmed
and chilled to the bone.
( chuckles )
I think we can handle her.
Zeus himself
watched over travelers.
We should follow his example.
Make yourself at home.
Thank you.
Where's your car?
Down the street
next to the coffee shop...
or what used to be
the coffee shop.
It looks like this whole town
is closed down.
It is.
Except for you, huh?
This ship will
never sink.
Right, Dad?
Decaf.
Not exactly
the nectar of the gods.
It'll do. Thank you.
What's this about,
if I may ask?
Preserving the past.
I'm Jason,
by the way.
Shannon O'Donnel.
I'm Henry...
Henry Janeway.
Hi. So you're trying
to get them
to stop building
this millennium whatever-it-is?
The Millennium Gate,
the world's first
self-sustaining
civic environment.
That's what
the propaganda calls it.
It's nothing
but hype.
It's actually
a glorified shopping mall.
They've talked
all of my neighbors
into selling their businesses.
Only one thing stands
in their way.
You're the last holdout?
This time,
Rome withstands the barbarians.
I may be able
to help you
if you'd be willing
to hire me.
Believe me, you don't want
to be licking stamps
for the next two days.
We could do all this
on a computer.
Yeah, but my dad doesn't
believe in computers.
We don't even have one.
Well, I do. We can e-mail
every computer
within a hundred
miles.
It'll just take
a few hours.
It's easy.
I'm not hiring anybody
right now.
Besides, you're going
to Florida.
Uh... maybe the tow
truck is waiting.
Thanks for
the coffee.
You're welcome.
I wouldn't ask you for a lot;
just enough to fix the car.
I really...
I kind of need
a job right now.
Dad?
I suppose we could use
some help.
You do believe in electricity,
don't you?
Yeah!
All right!
So who are these
"barbarians," anyway?
A company
down in Texas.
Well, why come here?
The city fathers
made it easy for them--
Free building permits,
deferred taxes, new roads--
So the invaders,
they return the favor.
They have offered us 20 percent
above the market price
for our properties.
You know what
the catch is?
We've all got to sell.
Everybody must love you.
Hmm, yeah.
The people I knew
when I was growing up--
Family friends-- It seems like
they've all turned against me.
If this were Roman times,
they'd feed me to the lions.
To the good old days.
You know, I was born
in the wrong millennium.
I'll stick with the modern age.
The classical age--
Greatest literature
mankind ever produced.
No antibiotics.
Families would take
care of one another.
No cars.
Air you can breathe.
No telephones.
What a pleasure.
Shorter life spans.
Lives that were
worth living.
No cold beer.
There you got me.
Speaking of the modern age,
do you have any plans
for the Millennium Eve?
No different than
last year's Millennium Eve.
I plan to be asleep.
Life of the party.
Don't tell me you bought
into all that hype again.
Oh, maybe
just a little.
Last year, when 2000 arrived?
Everyone was convinced
it was the dawn of a new era.
But when the world didn't end
and flying saucers didn't land,
and the Y2K bug didn't turn on
a single light bulb,
you'd think everybody would have
realized it was a number on a
calendar.
But, oh, no, they had to listen
to all those hucksters
who told them the real
millennium was 2001.
So this New Year's Eve
will be as boring as last year.
Come to think of it,
I have sold an awful
lot of doomsday books.
See what I mean?
So, what's in Florida?
I have a cousin down there.
I'll stay with her for a while
until I can get back on my feet.
If you don't
mind my asking,
did you lose your job?
I'm in a transitional period.
From what to what?
From what I was doing
to what I'm going to do.
Your son tells me
that your bookstore's
belonged in your family
for generations--
That you've never done
anything else.
Yes, that's right.
You know, I'm just the opposite.
I love to see places
I've never been,
try new things...
I'm kind of an explorer.
Really?
Hmm. That station
wagon of yours
doesn't exactly look
like a sailing ship.
It's a rocket ship.
My mistake.
We have every intention
of breaking ground
on Monday,
Day One
of the next millennium.
The people of this town
have given us
their full cooperation.
That's not true!
If you'll let me
finish, Mr. Janeway.
With the exception
of Mr. Janeway here.
Mr. Janeway, would
you like to comment?
Yes. Yes, I would.
You-you just can't...
you can't bulldoze
this town away.
This-this is our heritage!
This is our past!
We're trying to give
Portage Creek a future.
Can't you see that?
Yeah, yeah. Your future!
Your future! Not ours!
Mr. Moss, we've heard
that you're considering
moving the project to one
of your alternate sites.
Can you shed any light
on that rumor?
I'm afraid that's
more than a rumor.
If we can't work
out an arrangement
in Portage Creek,
we'll have no choice but
to select another location.
REPORTER: What city?
MOSS: No comment.
REPORTER:
Is it true that
Canton, Ohio,
has been chosen
for the alter...?
Thank you for your time.
Thank you, Mr. Moss.
Well, that's that.
All we have to do is stand
firm till New Year's.
Easy for you to say.
I have to go to school
with their kids.
Your school is one
of the first places
they're going
to tear down.
They said they'd build
a new one-- A better one.
Whose side
are you on?
I'm sorry.
We're all in
this together.
Come on.
Let's head back to civilization.
Where shall we dine
tonight?
Ah, how does Paris sound?
It's Friday night.
Can we get
a reservation?
Well, I think
I can arrange it.
I know the maitre d'.
Too bad I don't
speak French.
Well, we'll keep
it to ourselves.
There.
To new friends.
And a gracious host.
Bon appétit.
I wouldn't mind
visiting Paris one day.
Yes, it would be nice.
You haven't been?
I haven't been
outside Indiana.
These are my
traveling companions.
They'll take me
anywhere anytime.
It's not such a bad idea
to experience
the real thing
every now and then.
I prefer my books.
Maybe you just never
had the right guide.
Is that an offer?
I could make
a similar argument.
Not such a bad idea
to settle down
every now and then.
Is that an offer?
You're a peculiar man,
Mr. Janeway--
Cloistered away
with all your books...
shutting out the world...
Any more
peculiar than
exploring the Midwest
in an ailing station wagon?
Only slightly.
( chuckling )
Any word on my car?
It's got a brand-new oil pan.
You forgot to tell me that.
Well, we were busy today.
It's parked behind the garage--
Whenever you're ready.
First thing in the morning.
Not so fast.
Jason told me you promised
to show him a few tricks
on the computer.
I could use
another day of rest.
Great.
Jason'll be pleased.
And when you're done with him,
perhaps we'll take a stroll
along the Boulevard St. Germain.
You're making it difficult
to say goodbye.
Maybe that's the idea.
You wished to
see me, Captain?
I need your help
with this--
The Millennium Gate.
Impressive.
It was built by one
of my ancestors
over 300 years ago.
I've been
digging through
the historical
database,
but a lot of the information
from that era
has been lost or damaged.
I thought you might be able
to help me
reconstruct some of it.
Is this relevant to
our present mission?
It's relevant to me.
This ancestor of yours is
15 generations removed.
You only possess
a small fraction of
her genetic material.
Insignificant.
This isn't about
chromosomes, Seven.
It's about character.
Explain.
Shannon O'Donnel
inspired me
when I was a girl.
She had a...
an influence
on my imagination...
on my goals.
I never realized
genealogy could
have such an impact.
I wouldn't have become
a Starfleet Captain
if it wasn't for her.
Temple of Artemis
at Ephesus.
That's four.
The Colossus of Rhodes.
No, in chronological
order.
Right. Uh...
The Mausoleum
of Halicarnassus.
The Colossus
of Rhodes.
That leaves
just one more.
The seventh wonder of
the ancient world is...
Uh-huh. Can't remember?
Oh, it's right...
right on the tip
of my tongue.
It... la...
Forget it. I give up.
Ha! I got you.
It's the, uh...
Uh...
Can't remember?
The Lighthouse
of Alexandria
built by Ptolemy II
in 280 BC.
Behold the wonder
of the modern world--
Borg photographic memory.
We'll call this one a draw.
Brushing up on Earth's history?
Captain Janeway
requested that
I research one
of her ancestors.
Shannon O'Donnel.
You've heard of her?
Who hasn't?
You mind
if I lend a hand?
If you wish.
Sven "Buttercup" Hansen.
He was one of
my progenitors--
A 22nd century
prizefighter.
The Captain
encouraged me
to investigate my
genealogy, as well.
Well, your ancestors can
tell you a lot about yourself.
Somehow, I doubt "Buttercup"
has much relevance to me.
The connection could
be deeper than you think.
"Sven"... "Seven."
A coincidence.
The point is,
there's some of him in you,
just as there'll be some
of you in your descendants.
If I choose
to procreate.
Well, I wouldn't
dismiss it so lightly.
Someday, you might
enjoy a little
Seven of Nine point five
running around.
Or not. Or not.
My research
has failed.
I've found no references
to this individual.
Well, genealogy's
a lot like fishing--
You've... you've
got to cast a wide net.
Uh... computer,
expand record search
for subject
Shannon O'Donnel
to include
non-Federation databases,
personal archives,
and photographic
indexes, as well.
COMPUTER:
Reference found.
Take a look at this.
NEELIX:
Shannon Janeway.
Where in the world
did you find this?
NEELIX:
A Ferengi
database.
Ferengi?
11 years ago,
one of their historians
collected massive
amounts of data
about the origin
of space travel
in the Federation.
He wanted
to market it
as a nostalgic
gift item.
I would have been
his first customer.
It's a handsome family, Captain.
These must be her sons
and daughters...
grandchildren...
Great-grandchildren.
I've also discovered
journalistic accounts
in the historical
archives--
Mostly articles
concerning resistance
to the Millennium Gate.
The whole town
was against her.
Download this image for me,
will you, Neelix?
I'm going to frame it.
Yes, Captain.
The citizens of Canton, Ohio,
greeted Millennium Gate
representatives
with a small parade today.
Canton is one of three
alternate sites now being
considered by gate officials.
Vowing not to bow to pressure,
Henry Janeway, owner of Portage
Creek's Alexandria Books,
says he has no intention
of closing down.
Marci Collins,
Channel Three news.
"Next stop, Mars."
I used to be in
media relations with NASA.
As I recall, your class
came up with that slogan.
Do you mind?
It's a shame
you didn't make the cut.
Not good enough,
I guess.
Do you still keep in touch
with any of the others?
No.
I do.
In fact, I made
a few calls last night.
Remember Lieutenant McMillan?
How's she doing?
Copilot on a joint mission
with the Europeans
scheduled for '03.
Four months
on the space station.
Not bad for a girl
with claustrophobia.
She got over it.
Sorry to hear
about your last job.
All this downsizing
in aerospace...
Engineers aren't given
the respect they deserve.
Who told you I lost my job?
I made a few calls.
You don't have
to live like this--
Borrowing money,
sleeping in your car...
You've got no business
checking up on me.
Actually, I do.
We run a history
on all our candidates.
Are you trying to make me
some kind of an offer?
We know you've been working
closely with Henry Janeway.
He'll listen to you.
Oh.
You want me to talk to him--
Get him to change his mind.
If you can.
And in return?
We'd give you a job--
Make you a consulting engineer
on the project.
You certainly have
the credentials.
Well?
I'll think about it.
Think quickly.
We can't wait
another thousand years.
MISSION CONTROL:
Roger that and go ahead.
NEIL ARMSTRONG:
That's one small step for man...
one giant leap for mankind.
( keyboard keys clicking )
Morning.
I didn't think you'd mind.
You've got some really
great games on this thing.
Don't worry about it.
Have you tried Matrix of Doom?
Uh, yeah. I got vaporized
on level six.
Try launching a flare before
you enter the steel fortress.
Cool.
Coffee?
Please.
Where is your father?
Bloomington. All the suppliers
in town are boycotting us,
so he went up there
to place some orders.
He left you in charge?
Alexandria Books.
May I help you?
Sounds like
you've got it down.
I pay the bills too.
Dad's not very
good at accounting.
You have any kids?
Nope.
Not a priority?
I wouldn't say that.
I just never got around to it.
If you don't mind me asking...
where's your mom?
She died.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I was really young.
I don't remember her much.
Dad says none of
the great heroes
grew up in a
nuclear family.
Hercules, Achilles,
Odysseus--
They all grew up
with single parents.
You're in good company.
You like working here, Jason?
It's okay.
You know, I get the feeling
you don't share
your father's enthusiasm
about preserving the past.
I don't know.
The Millennium Gate
could be pretty cool.
Did you ever see the first
landing on the moon?
"One small step for man..."
They showed it in
science class one time.
I saw it on TV
when I was 11 years old.
The whole world watched it.
It must have been great.
Oh...
it was.
So do you have any heroes?
"We are not living
in a heroic age."
That's what my dad says.
Come on, there's
got to be somebody.
Dad.
I mean, he's a pain
sometimes, but...
he's pretty cool.
( phone rings )
Alexandria Books.
May I help you?
That's all right.
First call in three days
and it's a wrong number.
( chuckling )
Glorious Hector, son of Priam,
slips past
the Greek front lines,
bringing much-needed supplies
to the embattled city of Troy.
Hey, Dad--
You're famous.
"Local business owner
topples Gate."
Let it fall.
Any customers this morning?
No one here but
us galliforms.
That's "chickens" for the
nonscientists in the crowd.
You two are dangerous together.
Portage Creek will
thank us one day.
You don't sacrifice history
for a shopping mall.
It's a little more
than that, Henry.
I beg your pardon?
I said it's not
just a mall.
Have you read
the "promotional
literature"?
"Over 600 retail
spaces available.
Franchise potential."
There's a commercial
dimension to the project,
but that's not
its only function.
What's your point?
I've learned a few details
about the Millennium Gate.
It's a self-sustaining city,
an experimental biosphere.
It's never been done before.
What's wrong with the biosphere
we're living in now?
Nothing.
Exactly.
But this project
will help scientists
learn more about
our environment--
Possibly even recreate it
on other worlds.
Other worlds?
Don't we have enough problems
on the one we're on?
Yeah. Which is why I'd like
to get the hell off it one day.
I think
you're taking
this exploring
a little too far.
And you're so afraid of change,
you can barely walk
out that front door.
The Millennium Gate
has a lot of potential, Henry.
You just can't see it.
All you can see
is these books.
You're living in the past.
Sounds like you've been
sleeping with the enemy.
Having a beer, anyway.
Moss.
He offered me a job.
Doing what?
Consulting engineer.
On the Millennium Gate.
I said I'd think about it.
And he said, "Get Janeway
to sign on the dotted
line and you're hired."
That's one way
of looking at it.
And when I say no,
then what?
You're going to go
with them, right?
To Canton, Ohio,
or the Third Circle of Hell
or wherever it is they decide
to build this damn thing.
I can't keep living
out of my car.
You don't have to. Stay here.
No.
Why not?
Because I can't.
That's not a reason.
Because I don't want to.
You've been really
nice to me, Henry,
but I can't get stuck here.
"Stuck"?
Like me?
I didn't say that.
You can live
however you want to.
And so can you.
What's going on?
We're helping our guest
resume her journey.
But I thought you were
staying here for a while.
Something came up.
We can manage by ourselves.
I guess saying good-bye isn't
that difficult after all.
Jason.
Jason, where you going?
Aunt Pat's.
Happy New Year.
Jason!
It was around 2210.
My Uncle Jack was on
a deep space mission
to Beta Capricus.
That's when "deep space"
meant the next star over.
And that was when they still
had to go into stasis.
So Jack put his crew under
as soon as they left orbit
and piloted the ship
by himself for six months.
No contact with anybody
along the way?
There wasn't anybody
along the way.
Not back then.
The transmitter
wasn't even subspace.
It took weeks to get
a message back to Earth.
I would prefer stasis.
PARIS:
Me too.
That long alone,
I'd probably go
a little batty.
So six months
to Beta Capricus
and when they finally arrive...
there's nothing there.
No planets?
No. No star, no nothing.
It turns out Beta Capricus
was just an EM echo
of a distant galaxy.
What was his
course of action?
What else could he do?
He turned the ship around
and headed home.
And the crew?
He figured there was
no reason to bother them.
There's nothing to see,
nothing to do,
so six months later
he gets back to Earth,
brings everybody
out of stasis
and they wake up wondering
why they haven't left orbit.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Oh. I didn't realize
you were in a briefing.
Not at all. We're talking
about our family histories.
Oh. This can wait.
May I... join you?
Please.
I, too, come
from a distinguished line.
His cousin's
an electric shaver.
Hardly. My program was compiled
from the most advanced
holo-matrices in
the Federation.
My cousin was a prize-winning
chess program.
Ensign Paris,
you have yet
to elaborate
on your
family origins.
Well, they were
a pretty ordinary bunch,
salt-of-the-earth
type people.
Farmers, mostly,
some planetary colonists...
but there was one--
He was a pilot.
He flew the first orbital glider
over the lower Martian plateau.
Mars.
Your ancestor must
have known the Captain's.
She did work
on all the early Mars projects.
Looks like we go way back,
Mr. Paris.
What was her name?
Shannon O'Donnel.
O'Donnel...
Um...
I don't think so.
What do you mean?
I know all the Mars
projects from the 1970s on--
Unmanned, manned, who's who...
there were no O'Donnels
in any of them.
( door chimes )
JANEWAY:
Come in.
Ship's status report.
Let me guess.
The holographic engineer
is having problems
with her program;
Neelix, the Cardassian
cook, is low on supplies;
Seven of 12 is regenerating
and Captain Chakotay
is doing just fine.
Just wondering how they'll
piece together our lives
a few hundred years from now.
Depends on
how big the pieces are.
A padd here,
a Captain's log there,
maybe a couple of
holodeck programs.
It won't be as much to
go on as we might think.
I've gone through
dozens of histories
written about
21st century Earth.
All of them biased
in one way or another.
The Vulcans describe
first contact
with a "savagely
illogical" race.
Ferengi talk about
Wall Street as if
it were holy ground.
The Bolians express dismay
at the low quality
of human plumbing.
And human historians--
Exact same story.
Every culture saw it
a different way.
So I go back to
the raw material--
Birth certificates,
death certificates
marriage certificates,
census surveys,
voter registration forms,
housing records,
medical, employment...
court records.
It's all fragmented
and incomplete.
So... did she exist?
Her name was Shannon O'Donnel.
She did train to be
an astronaut...
but she didn't finish.
She was an engineer...
but never worked on
the Mars missions.
Did she work
on the Millennium Gate?
Only as a consultant.
What about all the opposition
you spoke of?
You said she fought
to get the project underway.
There was no opposition.
In fact, the Millennium Gate
was greeted with open arms
by the local population...
except for one man.
"Henry Janeway."
She married him...
and changed her name,
but she certainly
never changed history.
Don't be too hard on her.
She may not have known
she was supposed to live up
to your expectations.
Oh, I'll get over it.
But the question is:
When we get back to Earth,
how will I break the news
to Aunt Martha?
With less
than three hours to go,
Henry Janeway still refuses
to cooperate
with Millennium Gate
representatives.
I'll return with live updates
as midnight approaches.
Marci Collins,
Channel Three news.
ANNOUNCER:
This has been
a Channel Three Special Report.
I don't suppose there's any
chance he'll change his mind.
By midnight? Doubtful.
Then it looks like
we'll have to
scrub the launch.
At least where Portage
Creek is concerned.
It's a shame how one ignorant
man can stand in the way
of progress.
It's not that simple.
Henry's a very likable guy,
but he's playing
for the wrong team.
He's looking back.
This town needs people who
look towards the future.
Well, while you're
looking forward,
I'll be driving to Florida.
Wait a minute.
I'm not about to turn
a fellow explorer
out into the cold.
I didn't hold up
my end of the bargain.
If we didn't think
you had something to
add to this project,
we never would have made
the offer in the first place.
Henry Janeway's pigheadedness
doesn't change that.
We could still
use your help--
Just not here.
My associate in Canton.
I'll tell him
you're on the way.
He'll find
a place for you.
JASON:
Shannon!
What's the matter?
It's Dad.
See you in Ohio?
He won't leave the shop.
There's all these
people outside.
The police are there.
Your father can
take care of himself.
Please, won't you talk to him?
He'll listen to you.
No, he doesn't, Jason.
Where are you going?
And what's this about
"I'll see you in Ohio"?
Ohio... Florida...
What's wrong
with this place?
It didn't work out.
I thought
you liked us.
I do.
Then why are you leaving?
I'm sorry.
December 31, 2000.
11:15 p.m.
I've got 95 miles of interstate
before I have to decide
whether I head east or south,
but those 95 miles
won't be uneventful.
My guidebook tells me
that I'm not too far
from Leonardo da Vinci's
Last Supper...
re-created entirely in corn.
The last few days have been
memorable, to say the least.
I met Henry Janeway.
Interesting man.
Liked to talk.
Unfortunately, he doesn't listen
to anybody but himself.
He gave me a place
to stay, though...
and we had dinner...
in Paris, no less.
He has a son.
Good kid.
Bright, like his father.
MOSS:
I personally don't regret
a single day
I've spent in this lovely town,
and I want to thank you all
for your encouragement
and support.
REPORTER:
Would you consider
extending your deadline?
MOSS:
I'm afraid that's not possible.
We'd like to express
our deepest regret
to the town of Portage Creek
and on behalf of...
Excuse me.
Get this.
Let her through.
( knocking at door )
We're closed.
It's me.
I said, we're closed.
That's not what the sign says.
Damn it, Henry,
it's cold out here.
Who's with you?
Nobody but us galliforms.
Thought you'd be
in Ohio by now.
Car break down again?
What the hell
are you doing?
Get your things.
We're leaving.
I'm not going
anywhere.
Do I have to drag you
out the front door?
You can try.
Henry...
I won't leave.
It's over.
Well, then I'm going to have
to ask you to leave.
Half the town is out there.
You're on the news.
Maybe you'll even go
down in history.
You have made
your point.
Obviously, I haven't,
because if I had,
you wouldn't be asking me
to sign my life away.
Maybe if you'd looked up
from your books once in a while,
you'd see what's
in front of you.
Oh, please, no more
speeches about the future.
As long as I don't have to hear
you pontificate about the past.
It's a deal. Glad we had
this chat. Goodbye.
It's almost midnight, Henry.
Exactly. I've won.
What have you won? The right
to hide behind these shelves
for the rest of your life?
It's worked so far.
Well, it isn't working
for your son...
or this town...
or me.
Look, I know you've
got a job to do.
Oh, this isn't
about the job.
Then why are you here?
It was the cookies.
"Cookies"?
I was on the interstate.
I stopped for gas
and I bought a bag of
chocolate chip cookies
at a convenience store.
It's a little
ritual of mine.
Whenever I get back
on the highway,
I like to treat myself.
I see.
Well, uh...
what does this
have to do
with anything?
They didn't taste good, Henry.
It wasn't the same.
I just kept thinking about you
and how I wish
you'd been there.
Actually,
I prefer oatmeal cookies.
I'm allergic to chocolate.
Oh, you don't know
what you're missing.
It's been a long time...
but I'm starting to feel
like maybe
I found a place where...
I'd like to stick around
for a while,
with you and Jason.
And we'd like to have you.
But I can't work in a bookstore
for the rest of my life.
I've been given
a second chance, Henry,
and I can't lose that.
I'm stuck
in the future.
You're stuck
in the past.
But maybe we could... get
unstuck in the present.
I... I don't see how
with-without
sacrificing my...
You know, Mr. Moss
offered me
a job in Canton,
even though I failed
to keep up my end
of the bargain.
I guess he felt
sorry for me.
But I'm prepared
to turn him down...
if you want me to stay with you.
I suppose I could...
reopen my shop
in that monstrosity
you want to build.
Well, I'll have
a few connections.
I could probably get you
a nice remote location
so nobody would bother you.
Not much profit in that.
You sure you won't
drive away again?
No.
But if I do, we'll make
the trip together.
What time is it?
A minute to midnight.
Then we're not too late.
( door opens )
( cheering and applause )
Neelix to Captain Janeway.
Yes?
Captain, would you mind
coming to the Mess Hall?
Is there a problem?
No, no emergency.
But I need to speak with you.
A personal matter.
Give me a minute.
Happy Ancestor's Eve!
ALL:
What's all this?
It's April 22,
Ancestor's Eve.
It's a holiday
first established...
Well, uh, today actually
with the Captain's permission.
Neelix...
CHAKOTAY:
I think he's
onto something, Captain.
An evening
of reflection
in honor of those
who came before.
Hear, hear. Uncle Jack
would approve.
It got me out from
under a warp conduit.
I'm all for it.
I appreciate what you're
trying to do, but...
PARIS:
Neelix, the gift.
What gift?
Shannon O'Donnel Janeway,
circa 2050.
We did a little
more research.
This photograph was taken
in a small park
near Portage Creek,
38 years after
the dedication of
the Millennium Gate.
I thought it would look
nice in your ready room
on the shelf
next to your desk.
Thank you.
But I'm not so sure she
has a place there anymore.
You are mistaken,
Captain.
Oh?
Her life captured
your imagination.
Historical details
are irrelevant.
I concur
with that analysis.
CHAKOTAY:
If it weren't for
Shannon O'Donnel,
you never would have
joined Starfleet.
Yeah, and I would have never
got you all stuck here
in the Delta Quadrant.
It gave us all time
to get to know each other.
Time for a family portrait
of our own.
Everyone gather 'round
the Captain, please.
Face the camera.
Smile.
To family.
ALL:
Another one for posterity.
No, no...
PARIS:
I think we should
get out of here.
KIM: I don't think so.
JANEWAY: Enough is enough.
( camera shutter clicks )
Knock it off, Kieran.
That's an order.
( camera shutter clicks )