You're late.
Sorry, sir.
What's the threshold
of the H2 molecule?
14.7 electron volts.
Third brightest
star in Orion?
Viewed from where?
Earth.
Gamma Orionis,
or Bellatrix if you prefer
the original Arabic name.
Not bad.
Now, give me a hug, Katie.
That's an order.
I wasn't expecting a pop quiz.
Just wanted to make
sure all those pips
haven't made you forget
you're a scientist first.
How could they?
I still have nightmares about
your fractal calculus final.
( chuckles )
There's still some work
to be done,
but once the sawdust clears,
I think you'll be impressed.
Voyager may not be
as big as a
Galaxy-class ship,
but she's
quick and smart--
Like her Captain.
700,000 metric tons,
15 decks,
computer systems
augmented with
bio-neural circuitry.
Top cruising speed--
Warp 9.975.
Deck 1.
Of course, I expect to get
that up another notch or two.
Sounds like you already know
your ship pretty well.
I've been buried in
Voyager's schematics
for the past three months.
I could walk the corridors
blindfolded.
You might not want
to shut your eyes just yet.
Captain on the Bridge.
As you were.
It's bigger
than I expected.
Schematics never fully prepare
you for the real thing.
Try it on.
Don't get
too comfortable.
I have more to show you.
Your home away from home.
Coffee?
Oh, no, thanks.
Coffee. Black.
Any word from Tuvok?
Not yet.
Shouldn't he have
made contact by now?
We know he's aboard
Chakotay's ship.
He's probably decided
not to risk exposure
until he has to.
Catching up with him
in the Badlands
is going to be tricky,
even in a ship as quick
and smart as Voyager.
I've heard about a pilot
who might make the job easier.
Who's that?
Tom Paris.
Admiral Paris's son?
Correct me
if I'm wrong, but he's
serving a sentence for...
He's made some mistakes.
But everybody deserves
a second chance.
I'll look into it.
If it's not too late,
I'd like to recalibrate
the navigational sensors.
I think I can
enhance the range.
Your coffee's
not even cold,
you're already
making changes.
Excuse us, Ensign.
I like a ship that knows
where it's going.
I assure you, Voyager has
the best sensors in the fleet.
There's always room
for improvement.
( indistinct conversation )
The Bridge is clear.
There's no sign of the weapon.
MALE:
Continue scanning.
Acknowledged.
Your briefing room.
Starfleet's
most up-to-date vessel
and they still can't design
a comfortable place
to hold a meeting.
What do you
think, Ensign?
Captain?
What's your opinion
of this room?
It is an efficient design.
Well, there you
have it, Admiral.
It's efficient.
I must be wrong.
Carry on.
We've added
a new system
we're thinking of installing
throughout the fleet.
The Emergency
Medical Hologram.
I'm up-to-date.
Computer, activate EMH.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
It's programmed
with over four million
surgical procedures.
Five million and
the medical knowledge
of over 3,000 cultures.
Impressive.
Did you call me to chitchat
or is there
an actual emergency?
His personality
could use some work.
I'm designed
to practice
medicine as efficiently
as possible.
Small talk only compromises
my performance.
Thank you, Doctor.
Computer, deactivate EMH.
Thank you.
Hello.
Sir.
Lieutenant Carey.
I don't think
we've met.
Jameson, Anna.
Service number 860790.
I'm not security.
I'm just... trying
to get to know
all the new faces
around here.
What are you working on?
I am attempting to realign
the EPS manifolds.
Do you need a hand?
No.
Well, maybe I'll see you
in the Mess Hall later.
Unlikely.
Hmm?
I am not a member
of Voyager's crew.
I'm on assignment here
at Utopia Planitia.
Too bad.
Well... next time
I'm in the neighborhood,
I'll drop by and say hello.
I wish Starfleet would give me
more than three weeks.
With a little more time,
we could really
explore the Badlands.
You haven't
changed a bit.
Main Engineering.
Class-9 warp drive,
tricyclic
input manifold.
You'll be the first to
test it in deep space.
I've localized
the temporal distortions--
Deck 4, Section 39.
I've found the weapon.
MALE:
Begin the procedure.
( console beeping )
Problem?
One of the EPS relays
just went off-line.
Voyager's first malfunction.
I'm sorry, Captain.
I tested those systems
this morning.
As you were, Lieutenant.
I've been looking forward
to getting my hands dirty.
Hmm.
The weapon is out of phase.
You've sent me
to the wrong time frame.
MALE:
At least we know
where the weapon was placed.
Now we have to determine when.
This hatch is locked
from the inside.
This isn't
a secure area.
None of these hatches
should be sealed.
I'm reading some kind
of chroniton flux.
Chronitons?
It's coming from inside
this Jefferies tube.
Patterson to Security.
Seal off Deck 4.
( beeping )
I've been detected.
I must leave.
There's too much interference
from the weapon.
Recalibrate
your temporal transport beacon.
Understood.
We can access Section 39
through here.
MALE 2:
Scramble the locking mechanism
before they get in.
Hurry. They're approaching
your coordinates.
You'll need to reset
the command controls.
MALE:
Stand by. We're trying
to get you out of there.
MALE 2:
It's time.
Pull her out.
There's too much interference.
If I transport her now,
we'll damage
her bionetic implants.
If we don't, Captain
Janeway's going
to find her.
It'll contaminate
the timeline.
Sir...
Now.
MALE:
Temporal transport in progress.
Question, Admiral.
What causes
a chroniton flux of .003?
I don't know.
Neither do I, but whoever
or whatever it was...
it's gone now.
MALE:
The subject is approaching
the temporal threshold.
I told you
this was going to happen.
She's dead.
Any luck reviving her?
No, sir.
We'll have to
recruit her again.
Sir, a fourth jump,
she could suffer neural damage--
Even temporal
psychosis.
Unless we repair the timeline,
she's going to die.
We're giving her another chance
to save her crew and herself.
We'll go back
and retrieve Seven of Nine
a microsecond
before the explosion.
That way no one will
notice she's gone.
Tempus fugit, Lieutenant.
Raise shields.
Time frame-- Stardate 52861.274.
Delta Quadrant.
Spatial coordinates--
87-Theta by 271.
Target-- USS Voyager.
Follow the light
to the left,
right,
and up,
and down.
Hmm.
I ran
a complete self-diagnostic.
Mm-hmm?
At first, I thought
my ocular implants
were malfunctioning.
However, after
consulting
the Starfleet
medical database,
I realize it's a flaw
in my human physiology.
Specifically?
I'm experiencing
dizziness, double vision.
After considering
all potential environmental
and genetic factors,
I've concluded
that I am suffering
from Albright-Salzman syndrome.
A rare neurological condition
that hasn't affected
a single human being
for over two centuries.
Unlikely.
Human physiology is imperfect--
Susceptible
to a variety of disorders.
True, but in this instance,
we can safely say
you're suffering
from a mild case
of sensory aphasia...
a minor disruption
to your neuro-receptors.
Neither rare,
nor life-threatening.
Apparently I was in need
of a second opinion.
That's the danger
of self-diagnosis--
Patients always
assume the worst.
This should clear it up.
How do things look now?
Normal.
Doctor,
please report to Sick Bay.
On my way.
Next time your human
physiology fails you,
don't consult the database.
Just call me.
You are the database.
With two legs
and a splendid bedside manner.
A curious exercise.
Yeah, Ping-Pong.
You should try it.
It's a great test
of hand-eye coordination.
I don't require testing.
Yeah, so the Doc
tells me--
A visual acuity
index of 99.6.
You know, you'd be
great at this game.
Why don't you
be my partner
in the doubles
tournament tonight?
Chapman was supposed
to play,
but he's come down with
a nasty case of space sickness.
I'm busy.
Oh.
Too bad.
Well, I guess I'll have
to tell B'Elanna
that you thought
you couldn't beat her.
You're attempting to
appeal to my vanity.
Is it working?
I will consider
your request.
It's yes or no, Seven--
The tournament's tonight.
Yes.
Great.
Meet me in the Mess Hall
at 1900 hours.
We'll get in a little
practice first.
Captain, you don't
look well.
Come in, please.
I'm sure it's
nothing serious.
Symptoms?
Nausea, dizziness.
It looks like a simple case
of space sickness--
The third one
I've treated today.
That's odd.
We haven't run
into any turbulence.
It's possible
the inertial dampers
are out of alignment.
Even so, I've been
on some pretty rough rides.
It's never affected me
like this.
It happens
to everyone.
20 milligrams
of inaprovaline
should restore
your space legs.
I'll check the dampers.
Double-check your bio-readings.
See if there's
another explanation.
( groans )
Point, server.
It's all in the wrist.
Score?
19-18.
Say good night, Harry.
What do you call
that shot?
I'm reading
temporal distortions.
Report.
The temporal distortions
are fracturing space-time
throughout the ship.
Cause?
Unknown.
They appear to be emanating
from Deck 4, Section 39.
We've already
erected force fields,
but they're not
having much effect.
If we can't find
a way to stop them,
they'll tear
the ship apart.
How much time do we have?
Two hours,
at most.
Go to Deck 4 and find out
what we're dealing with.
Let's see if we can find a way
to enhance the force fields.
An injection a day keeps
space sickness away.
You try to be funny
after treating 37
cases of nausea.
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Go ahead.
We've found the source
of our epidemic--
Temporal distortions.
I was beginning to suspect
some kind of anomaly.
I've designed a treatment
that seems to be inhibiting
the symptoms.
Keep me posted.
Aye, Captain.
NEELIX:
Neelix to the Doctor.
I've got a medical emergency
in the Mess Hall.
Ensign Mannus
is violently ill.
On my way.
Take over here.
Doctor, shall I whip you
up a photonic snack?
Where's the medical emergency?
I hope you're not referring
to this pot roast.
You called me
a few minutes ago.
You said Ensign Mannus
was ill.
I did?
Yes.
Ensign Mannus is
right over there.
He came in
an hour ago.
He looks
perfectly norm...
Acute space sickness.
Good thing
you were here.
I wouldn't have been,
if you hadn't...
Temporal distortions.
Doctor?
This is all starting
to make sense.
In Sick Bay, it's
1500 hours, 43 minutes,
but in the Mess Hall,
it's 1536.
Seven minutes earlier.
I did get a
call from you.
You just haven't
made it yet.
Coffee, black.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Before you say anything,
let me remind you what happens
to bearers of bad news.
Don't kill the messenger.
Go ahead, fire.
It looks like these space-time
fractures are growing stronger.
We're detecting temporal
paradoxes throughout the ship.
Paradoxes?
Internal chronometers show
it's 0600 on Deck 9
and 0605 on Deck 13.
Time's passing more quickly
in some parts of the ship
and slowing down in others.
Maybe that explains
why this coffee
tastes like it's
three days old.
The same thing's been
happening in the Mess Hall.
Food replicated less than an
hour ago is already spoiled.
I've been working on a way to
enhance our containment fields
to keep the fractures
from spreading.
I'll get a team on it
right away.
In the meantime,
we should evacuate
the affected areas.
See to it.
There's one other problem.
Turbolifts...Turbolifts...
2 and 3...
2 and 3 are off-line...
are off-line... so we've
been using... so we've been
using... the Jefferies tube.
...using
the Jefferies tube.
Captain?
There's a temporal distortion
intersecting this room.
It's expanding.
Time to test your
new containment fields.
This is where
they're coming from.
I still can't tell
what's causing them.
What is it?
A piece of technology.
It's emitting
temporal distortions.
Why can't I see it?
My ocular implant
can detect
irregularities
in space-time.
Torres to Bridge.
We've found the problem.
There's some kind of device
in Junction Beta-28.
Beam it off the ship.
I can't get a lock.
The distortions are beginning
to demolecularize the hull.
Hull breach--
Ventral Section 14.
( alarm bleeping )
Captain, I'm picking up
a strange reading on Deck 4.
What kind of reading?
It's a chroniton flux--
.003.
CHAKOTAY:
More distortions?
I don't think so.
Dry dock.
Ma'am?
The first time
I saw these readings was...
five years ago?
Voyager was still
in dry dock.
Same readings,
same location.
What caused them?
I never found out.
We're losing
structural integrity.
Multiple breaches-- All decks.
Emergency systems are failing.
The distortions
are ripping us apart.
We have to abandon ship.
All hands, this is the Captain.
Proceed to the escape pods
and abandon ship.
Repeat: Abandon ship.
Program the pods for a heading
of 178 mark 4.
We'll rendezvous in orbit
of an M-Class planet
at those coordinates.
Repeat: All hands,
proceed to the escape pods
and abandon ship.
Identify yourselves.
No time.
( sighs )
Welcome back.
Why have you
brought me here?
For some reason, I always
think you'll remember.
I'm Captain Braxton.
This is
Lieutenant Ducane.
You're aboard the Federation
Timeship Relativity.
I'm no longer in
the 24th century.
No.
For you, it's almost
500 years later.
We've brought you here
to help us solve a mystery.
Someone--
We don't know who--
Has planted a weapon
aboard Voyager.
It's designed
to fracture space-time
within a radius of 150 meters.
Why do you need me?
Your ocular implant.
It can detect disruptions
in space-time
better than our sensors.
BRAXTON:
You're more familiar
with Voyager and her crew,
less likely to arouse suspicion.
So far you've been quite useful.
So far?
We've recruited you twice
before for this mission.
Take a look.
A force-3 temporal disrupter.
Your previous attempts
to disable it have
been unsuccessful.
DUCANE:
We're trying
to catch the saboteur
before he places the weapon
on Voyager.
Do you have a suspect?
Not yet.
Do you know
when the device was placed?
Not precisely, but we've
narrowed the window to a period
two years
before you joined the crew
when the ship was under attack.
Species 329-- The Kazon.
Our database indicates
that Voyager
was boarded twice
during that period.
The Kazon are
an inferior species.
They don't possess
the technology to create
such a complex weapon.
We believe the saboteur
infiltrated this time frame
because Voyager's shields
were down.
It was the perfect opportunity
to evade detection.
If I fail, you will
recruit me again.
If necessary.
But this will be
the third time
you're going to be removed
from your time frame.
If we do it a fourth,
there could be certain...
side effects.
Side effects.
You might experience
sensory aphasia.
It affects the cerebral cortex
and can lead
to temporal psychosis.
But in your case,
we're hoping third
time's a charm, eh?
I'll do my best.
Bring her up to date
on our protocols.
Aye, sir.
When you're finished here,
meet me in Holo-Matrix 1.
I've prepared
a simulation.
DUCANE:
Let's see how much
you've assimilated.
The Dali Paradox?
Also known as the
melting clock effect.
It refers to a
temporal fissure
which slows the passage
of time to a gradual halt.
The Pogo Paradox?
A causality loop
in which interference
to prevent an event
actually triggers
the same event.
Excellent.
Can you give me an example?
The Borg once
traveled back in time
to stop
Zephram Cochrane
from breaking
the warp barrier.
They succeeded,
but that, in turn,
led the Starship Enterprise
to intervene.
They assisted Cochrane
with the flight the Borg
were trying to prevent.
Causal loop complete.
So in a way,
the Federation owes
its existence to the Borg?
You're welcome.
The Seven of
Nine Paradox.
I beg your pardon?
How we do know that
my presence on Voyager
will not alter
the timeline?
You know, you've asked
me this every time?
What's been
your response?
That uncertainty is
part of the equation.
We don't know
what's going to happen.
I don't enjoy
uncertainty.
Neither do I, but I trust
Captain Braxton's instincts
just as you trust
Captain Janeway's.
BRAXTON:
This is a simulation
of Junction 49 on
Voyager's fourth deck.
Thanks to you, we've learned
that the temporal disrupter
was, and will be,
concealed here.
I gave up trying
to keep my tenses straight
years ago.
How will I disarm it?
You've already tried...
unsuccessfully.
The weapon's
out of phase.
You'll have to find
the saboteur
before he plants it.
This will detect
any chroniton flux
other than your own,
and I'm authorizing you
to use whatever force
may be necessary.
Understood.
One more thing-- Watch
out for the Janeway factor.
I am not familiar
with that protocol.
Your Captain has a knack
for sticking her nose
where it doesn't belong,
especially when it
comes to time travel.
Captain Janeway is
quite resourceful.
Has it occurred to you
that she may be helpful?
Helpful? That woman
has been responsible
for three major
temporal incursions.
No doubt creating
numerous paradoxes.
And who do you think
had to repair the damage? Me.
She's reckless;
she has no regard
for the integrity
of the timeline.
I asked for her help once.
She refused,
and I ended up stranded
in the late 20th century.
Have you ever been
to that time frame?
No.
Well, I don't recommend it.
After three decades with those
post-industrial barbarians,
I had to go through
extensive rehabilitation
before I could return to duty.
Avoid contact
with Janeway.
That's an order.
Yes... sir.
This will occlude
your Borg implants.
Ready?
Yes.
We have a saying
in our line of work:
"There's no time
like the past."
Raise shields.
Time frame-- Stardate
49123.5621. Delta Quadrant.
Spatial coordinates--
21 Alpha Prime by 936 Zeta.
Target-- USS Voyager.
CHAKOTAY:
All hands to battle stations.
We're under attack.
Repeat: All hands
to battle stations.
Return fire.
They're dropping
spatial charges.
Evasive maneuvers.
Shields down to 20 percent.
Another Kazon ship
is approaching.
Janeway to Engineering.
We need warp engines.
I can't give them to you--
Not until I've repaired
the containment generator.
Time?
I'll need ten minutes,
at least.
( console beeping )
Captain, I'm picking up
a strange reading on Deck 4.
What kind of reading?
It's a chroniton flux--
.003.
Any idea what's causing it?
Not yet.
It could be random interference
from Kazon
weapons fire.
I don't think so.
I've seen
these readings before.
There's no sign of the weapon.
Any uninvited guests?
Not yet.
The lead vessel's been disabled;
the others are regrouping.
B'Elanna, status?
Warp drive's on line,
but the containment field's
still unstable.
Warp 2 is the best
I can give you.
I'll take it.
Engage.
They're not pursuing.
Dry dock.
Ma'am?
The first time I saw these
readings was over two years ago
when Voyager was in dry dock.
Same readings, same location.
What caused them?
I never found out.
The signal vanished
before we could isolate it.
Erect a level-10 force field
around that section.
Is this really the
time to be chasing
sensor ghosts?
Something tells me
this is more than a coincidence.
Seal off Deck 4.
Tuvok, you're with me.
( alarm beeping )
They've erected force fields
around my location.
I may have been detected.
How shall I proceed?
( faint static )
Lieutenant, respond.
What's wrong?
The force fields are blocking
our transmissions.
Compensate.
Seven of Nine, report.
SEVEN:
Relativity, are you there?
It's no use, sir;
she can't hear us.
I don't believe
we've been introduced, Ensign.
Lower the force field.
I stand corrected.
We have met.
Utopia Planitia.
The briefing room.
You told me
it was "efficient."
Janeway...
You've mistaken me
for someone else.
Oh, I don't think so.
So here you are,
two years later
on the other side
of the galaxy.
Imagine that.
You are preventing me
from completing a vital mission.
Who are you, and what are
you doing on my ship?
Don't say anything.
She can't hear you, sir.
My designation is irrelevant,
but I assure you I have
no hostile
intentions.
Somehow, I don't find that
very comforting.
Are you working with the Kazon?
No, I am not.
I'm detecting
biomechanical implants.
They have a
Borg signature.
Janeway to the Bridge.
Scan the vicinity
for Borg ships.
CHAKOTAY: Did you say Borg?
Do it.
You will find none.
Then how did you get here?
I'm no longer Borg.
Then who are you?
I can't answer your questions.
Good.
JANEWAY: Why not?
It would be a violation
of the Temporal Prime Directive.
You're from another time?
Yes.
No...
JANEWAY: Who sent you?
I can't tell you that.
I would be risking damage
to the timeline.
I don't care if history itself
comes unraveled.
I want to know why
you're on my ship.
( beeping )
What's that?
You must release me.
Why?
Voyager is in grave danger.
So we've noticed.
Not from the Kazon,
from an act of sabotage.
I've been sent here to stop it.
The intruder has already
boarded the ship.
Please, your lives
depend on it.
You're not going anywhere until
you tell me what's happening.
My name is Seven of Nine.
I'm a member of your crew--
Rather, I will be
a member of your crew.
I've traveled back in time
to try to prevent a disaster
that will destroy Voyager.
Get her out of there.
I'm trying.
Let's see if I've got
this straight.
You're a Borg drone attempting
to prevent a disaster
that won't occur
for another three years.
Three years, six months,
and two days.
Does this make
any sense to you?
Like most time paradoxes,
it's implausible,
but not necessarily
illogical.
Captain...
when you take me from the Borg,
you are going to tell me
that part of being human
is learning to trust.
Trust me. Now.
Lower the force field.
Seven of Nine
to Braxton. Respond.
Stay where you are.
We're pulling you out.
That would be unwise.
I am pursuing the saboteur...
with Captain Janeway's
assistance.
Tempus fugit.
Proceed.
Yes, sir.
The intruder is
in Junction 52 Beta.
Take the starboard hatch.
Aye, Captain.
Captain Braxton...
Lower
the temporal disruptor.
It's armed.
I'll activate it.
Lower your weapons.
Janeway...
Have we met?
Too many times,
but you wouldn't remember.
They haven't occurred yet.
BRAXTON:
Seven of Nine, report.
I have located the saboteur.
Who is it?
It's you, Captain Braxton.
Me?
More accurately, a future you.
Now, let me complete
our mission.
Our mission? I don't know
what you're talking about.
Listen very carefully.
The circumstances
of your life
are going to change
in the next few years.
You'll be sent
into rehabilitation again,
forced to retire.
And it's all because of Voyager.
Captain, I believe
your future self
is suffering
from temporal psychosis.
Well, of course, I am,
you pedantic drone.
The only way for me...
for us to recover
is to obliterate Voyager
from the timeline.
That way, none of the events
that caused this illness
will have occurred.
What events?
30 years of exile
on 20th century Earth,
the temporal inversion
in the Takara Sector,
three violations
that I had to repair.
Can you get a lock on him?
DUCANE:
Negative. He's activated
a dispersal node.
I should say... you've activated
Don't be absurd.
I have no wish
to sabotage Voyager.
Not yet.
Remodulate the transporters.
Find a way to cut
through the interference.
I gave you an order,
Lieutenant.
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm taking command
of this vessel...
and I'm relieving
you of duty
for crimes... you're
going to commit.
I haven't done anything.
Seven of Nine...
apprehend Braxton.
No.
Relativity, he's escaped.
I'm tracking him.
He's traveled
to another time frame...
two years earlier.
Transport me
to those coordinates.
That would be
your fourth jump.
I am aware of the risks.
Stand by.
Thank you for your
assistance.
( groans )
There's still some
work to be done,
but, uh, once the
sawdust clears,
I think you'll
be impressed.
Voyager may
not be as big
as a Galaxy-class ship,
but she's...
Take cover!
Security, report to
Deck 4, Section 12.
Erect force fields around
all access points.
Is this part of the tour?
( grunts )
( groans )
SEVEN OF NINE: I've lost him.
He's still on Voyager,
but he's gone
five years ahead.
Initiate transport.
Point, server.
It's all in the wrist.
Score?
19-18.
Who are you?
Bridge, intruder alert,
Deck 2.
( groans )
Explain.
No time. You must
apprehend him.
He's trying
to destroy Voyager.
DUCANE:
Seven of Nine, status.
I am incapacitated--
It's sensory aphasia.
Stand by.
I'm pulling you out.
Stop him.
Your future depends on it.
Braxton?
I disabled his tricorder.
He's trapped there.
Seven of Nine
is pursuing him.
She is efficient.
She will succeed.
Let's hope so...
because we've
run out of options.
You again.
I don't believe
we've met, Ensign.
No, I'm wrong.
We have met.
Captain Braxton.
Not anymore.
I've lost my rank,
thanks to you.
Seven of Nine to Seven of Nine.
What's your status?
We've apprehended
Braxton.
How shall we proceed?
Stand by.
Long time no see.
Are you all right, Seven?
I believe we've
just prevented
Voyager's destruction.
Would you care
to explain how you...
The Timeship Relativity.
We need your help.
This Seven of Nine stopped
Braxton, but she created
several temporal incursions
along the way.
She instigated a phaser fight
at Utopia Planitia;
she was seen by you
and Lieutenant Tuvok
two years before
she joined your crew;
and she interacted
with her past self
in front of 15 crew members
at a Ping-Pong tournament
approximately
six minutes ago--
Your time frame,
of course.
Of course.
Needless to say, we need
to clean up the timeline.
Someone must go back
to the beginning
and prevent the chain of events
from occurring
in the first place.
I can't make another jump
without damaging myself.
I get the feeling
I'm about to be drafted.
In exchange for leniency,
Captain Braxton informs us
of the precise moment
he boarded Voyager
to plant the weapon.
We'll be sending
you to stop him.
Tell her.
Deck 4, Section 38.
I'll stumble over
a wounded crew member.
That will be your chance
to capture me.
Don't miss it, or we'll have
to do this all over again.
Wait a minute,
let me get this straight.
I'm going back in time
to stop Braxton...
But you already have him.
And there's a third one
in our brig.
I arrested him
earlier today.
But don't worry.
They'll all be reintegrated
in time for the trial.
And Seven?
Oh, I assure you
when all this is over,
there'll be just one
Seven of Nine.
All right.
Let's get started
before my headache
gets any worse.
TORRES:
Captain, a Kazon torpedo
just blew out the
containment generator.
Do you want me to
reroute emergency power
or take the warp core off-line?
Use your best judgment.
I thought you were on
your way to the Bridge.
I have to take care
of something first.
Now, get moving,
Lieutenant.
( doors open, close )
JANEWAY:
Send damage control teams
to Decks 9 through 14.
Seal the breaches if you can.
I'll be on the Bridge.
Keep me informed.
Yes, ma'am.
Come here often?
Incursion factor-- .0036.
That's better
than I expected.
Glad we could lend a hand.
When do we go home?
You'll both be returned
to your time frame.
You'll be
reintegrated
with the other
Seven of Nine.
Since none of
your time-jumps
were to your foreseeable
future-- Only the past--
I see no reason to resequence
your memory engrams.
But remember the Temporal
Prime Directive.
Discuss your experiences
with no one.
Understood.
Oh, Captain...
Braxton was right
about one thing--
Voyager shows up on our sensors
far too often.
Try to avoid time travel.
See you in the 24th century.
I look forward to it.
Or should I say backward?
Don't get started.