( dramatic theme playing )
Stay the course!
( console beeping )
Shields are down to 29 percent.
They're breaking through.
Let them!
Sir?
Take the shields offline
and recharge the emitters.
That'll bring them up
to full power.
The charging cycle takes 45
seconds. We'll be vulnerable.
We'll be dead if we don't get
the shields back up.
Arm yourselves!
Drop shields!
( console beeps )
( shields power down )
Recharge cycle?
Thirty seconds.
( whirring )
There!
Time?
Ten seconds.
( high-pitched screeching )
( screaming )
( screeching )
( triumphant theme playing )
( muddled ):
This is Captain Ransom
of the Federation Starship
Equinox.
We're under attack.
We need assistance.
This is Captain Ransom of the
Federation Starship Equinox.
We're under attack.
We need assistance.
Ransom.
He was in command of a science
vessel, the Equinox.
His distress call
was transmitted
approximately
14 hours ago.
Distance?
3.2
light years.
Try to get a fix on
their location.
CHAKOTAY:
What's it doing
in the Delta Quadrant?
Perhaps it's searching
for Voyager.
The Equinox is
a Nova-class ship.
It was designed
for planetary research,
not long-range
tactical missions.
I've got their
coordinates.
Heading 258
mark 12.
Set a course, maximum warp.
Go to red alert.
Hang on, Captain.
Did you know
this individual?
JANEWAY:
Only by reputation.
He was an exobiologist,
promoted to Captain
after he made first contact
with the Yridians.
Species 6291.
The collective determined
that they were extinct.
So did
the Federation.
Ransom proved
otherwise.
I always wanted
to meet him.
Too bad it won't be under
better circumstances.
I look forward to meeting
him as well and his crew.
I wish to expand
my knowledge of humanity.
Let's hope
you get the chance.
( dramatic theme playing )
We're approaching
the coordinates.
Take us out of warp.
KIM: I've got them.
2,000 kilometers
off the port bow.
They're moving
at low impulse.
Intercept.
Can you get a visual?
( beeping )
TUVOK:
They are heavily damaged.
Multiple hull breaches.
Warp drive
is offline.
What's happening
to their shields?
They're being disrupted
by some kind of energy surges.
Weapons fire?
There are no other ships
in the vicinity.
We're in hailing range.
JANEWAY: Open a channel.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
We're responding to your--
RANSOM:
Voyager! You've got to extend
your shields
around our ship.
Match the emitter frequency.
Are you under attack?
RANSOM: Shields! Quickly!
Do it.
( dramatic theme playing )
We're in position.
I'm attempting to match
their shield frequency.
( whirring )
Do you hear
something?
( whirring intensifies )
( console beeping )
Interspatial fissures are
opening on Decks 10, 6 and 1.
Tuvok.
Stand by.
Shields
are holding.
The fissures?
No sign of them.
Voyager to Ransom.
Captain.
( static )
Assemble rescue teams.
Secure the Equinox.
Tuvok,
you're with me.
( alarm blaring distantly )
( ominous theme playing )
CHAKOTAY:
Hello?
Is there anyone here?
( ominous theme playing )
See if you can bring
main power online.
Tom.
( beeping )
CHAKOTAY:
What happened?
Some kind
of thermalytic reaction.
It's desiccated
every cell in that body.
B'ELANNA:
Commander.
I can't make heads or tails
of this injector manifold,
and it looks like
the dilithium matrix
has been completely
redesigned.
We'll try to find one
of their engineers to help us.
In the meantime,
see if you can bypass the core.
Aye, sir.
( gasping quietly )
Hang on.
( grunts )
( grunting )
I'm Commander Chakotay,
USS Voyager.
But...
But we're the only humans
in the Delta Quadrant.
That's what
we used to think.
Come on.
( groaning )
KIM:
Over here!
( sighs )
Hang on.
We're getting you out of here.
I don't believe
we've met.
Ensign Kim...
And this is
Seven of Nine.
I have to cut him out
with a plasma torch.
Talk to him.
Keep him calm.
State your name.
Lessing...
Noah.
What are you doing
on this side of the galaxy?
The answer
is complicated.
Do me a favor?
See if my legs
are still there.
I haven't felt them
in two days.
SEVEN:
Your limbs are intact.
Thank you.
KIM:
Seven,
give me a hand.
Do not be frightened.
Too late for that.
( beeping )
I'm picking up
life signs.
NEELIX:
Hello?
Is there
anyone here?
No!
We're here
to help you!
Take cover!
We're
under attack!
( grunts )
( machines beeping )
Neelix
to Sickbay.
DOCTOR:
Sickbay here.
We've found
another survivor.
His wounds
are not serious,
but he's suffering
from psychological distress.
DOCTOR:
Acknowledged.
( ominous theme continues )
( beeping )
( groaning )
( grunts )
( sighs )
My crew.
You took
heavy casualties.
We're treating the survivors.
Who attacked you?
We don't know.
We can't communicate
with them.
They've been attacking us
for weeks.
( breathing heavily )
Easy. Easy.
( moans )
I've got to secure
the ship.
Leave that to us.
No.
Treat me here.
I'm not leaving
my Bridge.
I can't pull rank on you,
Captain,
but you're in no condition
to put up a fight.
( sighs )
So...
How's Earth?
I wish I could say.
( continues breathing
heavily )
You weren't sent here
to find us?
I'm afraid not.
We've been stranded in the
Delta Quadrant for five years.
We were pulled here against our
will by an alien called
BOTH ( in unison):
the Caretaker.
We'll compare notes
later on.
Let's get you
to Voyager.
We're here to commemorate
our honored dead.
Lieutenant
William Yates,
John Bowler...
Ensign
Dorothy Chang...
Edward Regis...
And Crewman David Amanti,
who all served
with distinction.
Their bravery
and sacrifice
will not be forgotten.
They will be
missed.
But now,
there is cause
for optimism.
Captain Janeway,
Voyager...
On behalf of
my crew...
thank you.
We'll have time to give
the newest members
of our family
a proper welcome
in the days ahead,
but right now,
we've got our hands full.
The Equinox is secure,
but its primary systems
are still badly damaged.
Harry, B'Elanna,
make it your priority.
Captain Ransom
has provided us with data
regarding
the alien attacks.
Tuvok, Seven,
you'll be working with
First Officer Maxwell Burke.
To kindred spirits...
may our journey home
together be swift.
Dismissed.
We should begin by familiarizing
you with Voyager's defenses.
Can you give me
a minute?
There's someone I'd like
to say hello to first.
We'll be in
the Astrometrics Lab.
Deck 8,
Section 29.
See you there.
BLT.
Max...
I tried to say
hello in Sickbay,
but you
were sedated.
I remember.
I thought I was dreaming.
( sighs )
So...
where's my sweater?
The blue one?
Class insignia
on the back?
We went to
the Academy together.
Ah...
Maxwell Burke.
Tom Paris.
Harry Kim.
Welcome aboard.
First Officer. Impressive.
The last time we talked,
you were about to drop
out of Starfleet.
I heard you beat me to it...
The Maquis?
For a while.
Until I ran into
these two.
( chuckling )
And it's been
hell ever since.
Well, I told
your resident Vulcan
I'd be
right with him.
Are you free later?
I'd love to catch up.
Why don't we all
have dinner together?
Sounds great.
( door opens, closes )
( sighs )
"BLT"?
Bacon, lettuce and tomato.
It was a nickname.
A nickname?
My initials.
Oh...
How romantic.
We broke up
over ten years ago.
No need
to go to red alert.
How about
yellow alert?
You're cute
when you're jealous.
Who's jealous?
See you on the Equinox.
Well,
Turkey Platter,
what do you say
we go to work?
Who's jealous?
Commander?
Um...
I've been assigned to one
of the repair crews
on the Equinox,
and I was wondering
if I could join
a different team...
Maybe one on Voyager.
Problem?
Just a little post-traumatic
stress syndrome.
Bad memories.
A few.
Actually,
I could use someone
with your
engineering abilities.
Well, thank you.
Such a clean ship.
I'm used to falling bulkheads
and missing deck plates.
In a few weeks, you won't
even recognize the Equinox.
You'll be happy
to go back.
Unless I stay.
You said you
could use someone
with my
engineering abilities.
I don't think your Captain
would appreciate that.
He's got a skeleton crew
as it is.
Engineering's
five decks down.
It's a long crawl through
the Jefferies tubes.
Deck 11.
( beeps )
I haven't set foot
in a turbolift
in over
three months.
Claustrophobia?
If one of those fissures
opened up in here,
where would
we take cover?
( whooshing )
It's only a graviton relay,
nothing to worry about.
Do I look worried?
( whirring )
Emergency stop!
( beeps )
Um,
if you don't mind,
I think I'd rather take
the Jefferies tube.
I could use
the exercise.
I've run a thermographic
analysis of our shields.
It revealed multiple
stress points.
We believe
they're the result
of alien attempts
to infiltrate our vessels.
TUVOK:
Each time a fissure opens
within a meter of
our shields,
it weakens them by
0.3 percent.
At the present rate,
we have less
than two days
to mount a defense.
According to
your bio-scans,
the aliens can
survive in our realm
for only
several seconds.
They're like fish
out of water,
but they can do a lot
of damage in those seconds.
Nevertheless,
it is a tactical weakness.
Perhaps we can
exploit it.
What have you got
in mind?
If we can show them we have
the ability
to hold them here,
they'll think twice
before launching
another attack.
JANEWAY:
But the question is,
how do we catch these fish?
You build a net.
Commander?
A multiphasic force field to be
exact. We wanted to see what we
were up against, so we built
a small chamber that could keep
one of them trapped
for several minutes.
If we could expand on
that technology,
we might be able
to create a latticework
of multiphasic force fields
around both ships.
Rudy?
If Captain Janeway agrees.
We'll need to examine
that stasis chamber.
I'm afraid that
won't be possible.
It's in our
research lab.
That whole section
was flooded
with thermionic radiation
during the last attack.
It'll be days before
anyone can go in there.
The design schematics
are in our auxiliary datacore.
I'll see if I can download them.
You give me a hand?
( tranquil theme playing )
I couldn't help
but notice your crew
calls you by
your first name.
When you've been
in the trenches
as long as we have,
rank and protocol are luxuries.
Besides, we're a long way
from Starfleet Command.
I know the feeling.
You seem to run
a pretty tight ship.
We've been known to let our hair
down from time to time,
but I find that
maintaining protocol
reminds us of where
we came from
and, hopefully,
where we're going.
It seems to work
quite well for you.
Oh, we've overcome
our share of obstacles,
warp core breaches,
ion storms,
a few rounds with the Borg.
The Borg?
We haven't seen so much as a
cube since the day we arrived.
Consider yourself lucky.
Have you ever run into
the Krowtonan Guard?
Never heard of them.
That's how we spent our first
week in the Delta Quadrant.
They claimed we violated
their territory.
I gave the order
to keep going.
I lost 39,
half my crew.
I'm sorry.
We never recovered
from that loss.
It changed everything.
What do you mean?
When I first realized
that we'd be traveling
across the Delta Quadrant
for the rest of our lives,
I told my crew that we had
a duty as Starfleet officers
to expand our knowledge
and uphold our principles.
After a couple of years,
we started to forget that
we were explorers.
Then there were times when
we nearly forgot
that we were human beings.
This is a Nova-class
science vessel
designed for short-term research
missions, minimal weapons.
You can't even go faster
than warp 8.
Frankly, I don't know
how you've done it.
You've obviously traveled
as far as we have
with much fewer resources.
I wish that I could take
all the credit,
but we stumbled
across a wormhole,
and made a few enhancements
on our warp engines.
I'd like to ask you something,
captain-to-captain.
Mm-hm.
The Prime Directive...
how often have you
broken it,
for the sake of
protecting your crew?
Broken it?
Never.
Bent it on occasion.
And even then,
it was a difficult choice.
What about you?
I've walked the line
once or twice...
but nothing serious.
There you are.
( tranquil theme playing )
It's a good omen.
Let's put it back
where it belongs.
I thought
I'd find you here.
How could I resist after
two years on emergency rations?
Don't get
too comfortable.
( sighs )
If Janeway's
any indication,
these people
will never understand.
They're going
to find out eventually.
Not if we keep them
out of the research lab
and away from
the warp core injectors.
And be careful what you say
around their crew...
And that includes
old girlfriends.
Understood.
( tranquil theme turns
dramatic )
Mm...
Not bad.
How's my angel
of mercy?
Crewman Lessing.
I didn't expect you
to recover so quickly.
You have
an outstanding EMH.
Ours can barely hold
a laser scalpel.
The doctor
is efficient.
I've been assigned to help you
sort through our biodata.
You saved my life.
The least I can do is
save you a little time.
( whirring )
( console beeping )
Lateral shields are offline.
How's that possible?
Fissures are opening on
Decks 1, 8 and 11.
Reroute power!
( whirring fades away )
What happened?
Apparently, the aliens began
to focus their attacks
on a single shield vector.
It collapsed
before the auxiliary emitters
could respond.
It looks like they've changed
their tactics.
We may have less time
than we thought.
( dramatic theme playing )
SEVEN:
We've examined
the schematics
of your
multiphasic chamber.
It can
be adapted.
We intend to
create
an auto-initiating
security grid.
TUVOK:
The moment an alien
invades either ship,
a force field
will surround it.
Once we modify
our field generator to emit
multiphasic
frequencies,
it will power the security
grids on both ships.
How long will
it take?
Approximately
14 hours.
We don't know when they'll break
through again. We may not last.
CHAKOTAY:
We could cut the time
in half if we
evacuate all personnel
from the Equinox,
and focus our efforts
here on Voyager.
Remember,
we are still
35,000 light years
from Earth.
We should try
to preserve both ships.
With two vessels, we'd be able
to pool our resources,
doubling our chance at
finding a shortcut home.
Normally, I'd agree,
but right now,
one of our ships
is vulnerable.
Chakotay's right.
We should make
our stand on Voyager.
I don't want
to force the issue,
but I am prepared
to return to the Equinox
with my crew.
What is the protocol
in this situation?
We have two Captains
and two ships.
Who gets the last word?
Starfleet Regulation 191,
Article 14.
"In a combat situation
involving more than one ship,
command falls to the vessel
with tactical superiority."
I looked it up this morning.
Good thinking.
In this case, protocol
recognizes my authority.
Are you ordering me
to abandon my ship?
I'd rather not have to.
And that protocol was written
in the Alpha Quadrant.
I'm not so sure that it makes
much sense out here.
The regulation stands.
Who am I
to dispute protocol?
Give Captain Janeway
your full cooperation.
Rudy...
Max, that's an order.
We'll get through this.
If that's all,
Captain,
I'd like to return
to my quarters
and collect
a few mementos.
By all means.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
( console beeping )
Intruder alert.
Same old Max,
going through my things.
That is
a command station.
It's off-limits without
my direct authorization.
I didn't realize.
You gonna throw me
in the brig?
I think we can overlook
this infraction.
Can I help you
with something?
I'm just doing some homework,
studying your propulsion system.
If there's a chance I'm gonna
be stuck on Voyager,
I figured I'd better
learn my way around.
Maybe you could tutor me
over dinner.
Problem is...
you were never really
interested in the work.
Or the meal.
( chuckles )
Something tells me
you haven't changed.
You'd be surprised.
I'm not the...
What did you once call me?
Pahtk.
Pahtk. I'm not the pahtk
I used to be.
Let me prove it
to you.
Look, Max...
Don't get me wrong.
It's good to see you again,
but ten years...
Tom Paris.
You could do worse.
So we're still on
for dinner?
Just the two of us?
Get going...
or I will throw you
in the brig.
Before we abandon
the Equinox,
we should try to salvage
any useful components.
Let's start with
your dilithium crystals.
Mm, what we have
left of them.
I'm afraid we only
have a few isograms.
That's barely enough
to power the sonic showers.
Can I make a suggestion?
Please.
Let's forget about
the primary systems.
They're too badly damaged.
Let's focus on supplies.
We picked up a few items
I think might come in handy,
Uh... Two kilotons
of kemacite ore,
a dozen canisters
of mercurium.
Tell Neelix to make room
in Cargo Bay 1.
Right.
Could you use
a synaptic stimulator?
Depends.
What is it?
It's a neural interface
you wear behind your ear.
It taps into
your visual cortex
and shows you
different alien vistas.
Just think of it as
a poor man's holodeck.
So that's how you
kept yourself entertained.
Beats checkers.
The Ponea gave it to us.
Never heard of them.
We call them the life of
the Delta Quadrant.
They see every first contact
as an excuse to throw a party.
( all chuckle )
I wish that we...
had encountered
more species like that.
You're the first
friendly faces
we've seen in months.
I'm glad we found you.
The feeling is mutual.
Those modified plasma injectors
looked elaborate.
What were you trying
to do?
Uh...
We were experimenting
with ways to enhance
our warp drive. It didn't work.
Maybe we should let
B'Elanna take a look.
It won't work.
Um...
We tried for months.
NAOMI:
Excuse me.
Oh, hello,
there.
Commander,
permission to interrupt?
Granted.
Ensign Gilmore.
That's right.
Naomi Wildman,
Captain's Assistant.
GILMORE:
Is that so?
I wanted to officially welcome
you aboard the Starship Voyager.
I'm glad to be here.
If you need anything,
replicator rations,
a tour of the lower decks,
I'm your man.
Thank you, Miss Wildman.
I'll keep that in mind.
As you were.
( chuckling )
I didn't realize that
you had children on board.
Only one.
She was born here.
Mmm. I have a nephew
back on Earth...
The same age.
Well...
Not anymore.
I guess
he's a teenager by now.
I probably wouldn't even
recognize him.
You'll see him again.
( comlink beeps )
RANSOM: Ransom to Gilmore.
Yes, Captain.
RANSOM:
Report to the Equinox Bridge.
On my way.
Duty calls.
Assemble a salvage team.
Aye, sir.
( dramatic theme playing )
BURKE:
Once we take their field
generator, we'll part company.
What happens
to Voyager?
They have weapons, shields, a
full crew. They'll survive.
Maybe we should
abandon ship...
Try to forget everything
that's happened here.
A shower
and a hot meal.
I guess that's all it takes
for some of us to forget
what's at stake here.
We're going home.
We can't let Voyager
stop us now,
not when we're this close.
Now, we're proceeding
as planned.
Are there
any other objections?
I need each and every one of you
to give me your very best...
As you always have.
Max.
This won't be easy.
The generator
is located on Deck 11,
next to the
warp plasma manifold.
We can't get a clean lock
without boosting the signal.
Marla, we need you to set
aside your claustrophobia
and crawl through
the access port
and set up the
transport enhancers.
Understood.
We'll have to take
the internal sensors
in that section off-line.
Noah,
you're elected.
You can count on me, sir.
I'll disengage
the power couplings
from Engineering.
( sighs )
You'll all have time for one
last shower.
Make the most of it.
There's a minor
power fluctuation
in the
security grid.
It's within
tolerance.
I believe
I can correct it.
The discrepancy is in
the Equinox research lab.
If we can determine
the exact frequency
of their
multiphasic chamber,
I will tune our
field generator to match it.
There are times when perfection
hinders efficiency.
This is odd.
The lab
is still permeated
with high levels
of thermionic radiation.
It should have
dissipated by now.
I believe
I have an explanation.
Three EPS conduits
have been rerouted to the lab.
It appears they are
emitting the radiation.
TUVOK:
The lab was contaminated
intentionally.
Any theories?
Only one.
Ransom doesn't want us
to enter the research lab.
He has been
adamant about
protecting his ship.
I thought it was simply
a Captain's pride.
I want to take a closer look
at that lab.
If we close off
those EPS conduits, how long
will it take to vent
the radiation?
Several hours.
I don't wanna wait that long.
Send the doctor.
He'll be immune to
its effects.
Tell him to look for anything
out of the ordinary.
Monitor his progress
from Astrometrics.
Shall I notify
Captain Ransom?
Not yet.
I want to wait
until we test your theory.
( dramatic theme playing )
DOCTOR:
I'm in.
( dramatic theme grows
ominous )
I've found
the multiphasic chamber.
There's some kind
of organic mass inside.
It appears to be a member
of the alien species,
but its cell structures
have vitrified.
This is more than just
a stasis chamber.
It's some kind of
matter-conversion technology.
Hold on.
There's a control port here.
Hm.
Doctor?
DOCTOR:
The chamber contains
a polaron grid
and a sub-molecular
resequencer.
It looks like
it was designed
to convert
the alien cell structures
into some kind
of crystalline compound.
That function was not
specified in their schematics.
I have a feeling there's
a lot here they didn't specify.
I've accessed
their research logs.
They're encrypted, but judging
by the file headings,
they've performed this procedure
dozens of times.
( beeping )
More of
the alien compound.
But it's been
biochemically altered.
They've extracted
the base proteins.
( beeping )
Its molecular structure
is most unusual.
Can you be
more specific?
DOCTOR:
It appears to store
a great deal
of nucleogenic
energy.
I'm no engineer,
but I'd say
they were trying
to convert this material...
into a source of power.
( dramatic theme playing )
I'm going
to miss this ship.
Once we get back to Earth,
there'll be plenty of women.
Status?
Ready on all fronts.
The transport enhancers
are in place and Noah's created
a subroutine to mask Voyager's
internal sensors.
Power couplings?
Bypass controls have been
routed to our Bridge.
All you need to do
is say energize.
Janeway wants to bring on
the security grid
at 1900 hours.
We'll have to act
before then.
Tell the others
to be prepared to...
Max.
The Transporter Room's not far
from here. Keep moving.
Captain Janeway wishes
to speak with you.
JANEWAY:
The alien compound.
Ten isograms.
If I understand
your calculations,
that's enough to increase
your warp factor by,
what, 0.03 percent
for one month?
Unfortunately, that boost
wouldn't get you very far.
So you'd need to replenish
the supply.
And that means
killing another lifeform.
And then another.
How many lives
would it take to get you back
to the Alpha Quadrant?
I think you know
the reason we're under attack.
These aliens are trying
to protect themselves from you.
Sixty-three. That's how many
more it will take.
Every time I sacrifice
one of those lives,
a part of me
is lost as well.
I might believe that if I hadn't
examined your research.
These experiments
were meticulous,
and they were brutal.
If you'd felt any remorse,
you'd never have continued.
Starfleet Regulation 3,
Paragraph 12.
In the event
of imminent destruction,
a Captain is authorized
to preserve
the lives of his crew
by any justifiable means.
I doubt that protocol
covers mass murder.
In my judgment,
it did.
Unacceptable.
We had nothing.
My ship was in pieces.
Our dilithium was gone.
We were running on
thrusters.
We hadn't eaten
in 16 days.
( sighs )
We had just enough power
to enter orbit
of an M-Class planet.
And lucky for us,
the inhabitants were generous.
They were called the Ankari.
And they provided us
with a meal
and a few supplies,
even some dilithium crystals.
They even performed one
of their sacred rituals
to invoke spirits
of good fortune
from another realm
to bless our journey.
But these weren't spirits.
They were
nucleogenic lifeforms.
Our scans revealed
that they were emitting
high levels of antimatter.
Later that same night,
we managed to obtain
one of the summoning devices
in exchange for
an energy converter.
We constructed
a containment field
that would prevent
the lifeform
from vanishing so quickly.
But something went wrong.
( screeching )
Get it
out of there.
RANSOM:
We tried to send it back.
( screeching )
We can't.
RANSOM:
But it was too late.
We examined the remains
and discovered
it could be converted to enhance
our propulsion systems.
It was already dead.
What would you
have done?
We traveled over
10,000 light years
in less than two weeks.
We'd found our salvation.
How could we ignore it?
By adhering to the oath
you took as Starfleet officers.
to seek out life,
not destroy it.
It's easy to cling to principles
when you're standing on a vessel
with its
bulkheads intact,
manned by a crew
that's not starving.
It's never easy,
but if we turn our backs
on our principles,
we stop being human.
I'm putting an end
to your experiments,
and you are hereby relieved
of your command.
You and your crew
will be confined to quarters.
Please,
show them leniency.
They were only following
my orders.
Their mistake.
( dramatic theme playing )
It's a long way home,
Captain.
( door closes )
Doctor,
return to their research lab
and retrieve all the data
you can locate on the aliens.
I wanna find a way
to communicate with them.
Aye, Captain.
Go to their engine room.
Take those warp core
modifications offline.
Captain?
Let's try to make first contact
the right way.
What's going
to happen to us?
That's up to
Captain Janeway.
You'll be confined
to quarters
until we can find
a way to make peace
with these lifeforms
you've been killing...
if it's not
too late.
To be honest,
I'm glad you stopped us.
Living the rest of my life
knowing what we'd done.
You could've
stopped yourself.
Why didn't you?
I don't know.
When the Captain ordered me
to modify the warp core,
I concentrated
on the work.
I tried not to think about
how it was gonna be used.
Well, think about it now
because we need your help.
Commander?
After you.
We're having trouble
making sense of all this.
SEVEN:
The schematics are encrypted.
I can't access them.
Do you know
the decryption codes?
Your Captain's
been relieved of command.
You take orders
from me now.
Do you have
the codes?
Yes.
Proceed.
Think of it this way,
Ensign.
You might live with yourself
a little easier.
( dramatic theme playing )
( beeping )
GILMORE:
You said you
wanted to learn
more about humanity.
I guess we're not
exactly prized examples.
I'm sorry.
On the contrary.
You've taught me
a great deal.
Computer, I decrypted this data
file. Why can't I access it?
COMPUTER:
EMH authorization
is required.
Is your EMH
still functional?
Affirmative.
Activate him.
Please state the nature
of the medical emergency.
I require your assistance.
Who are you?
Your counterpart from
the Starship Voyager.
Where's Captain Ransom?
My crew?
In custody.
How were you able
to leave your Sickbay?
This device allows me
to go anywhere I please.
In case you weren't aware,
your crew has been running
criminal experiments here.
I know.
I designed them.
You?
That's a violation
of your programming.
They deleted
my ethical subroutines.
( ominous theme playing )
I'm picking up spatial fissures,
hundreds of them.
Looks like they've
stepped up their attacks.
Reroute all available power
to shields.
They're holding,
but at this rate,
it won't be long
before the aliens
break through.
Bridge to Tuvok.
We need that security grid.
We're preparing
to bring it online.
Charge the emitters.
Bridge to the doctor.
DOCTOR 2: Sickbay here.
Did you find anything?
Could you be...
more specific?
Neural patterns, cortical scans,
anything that could help us
program
the universal translator.
Negative. I couldn't access
the Equinox data files.
They were encrypted.
Keep studying
the information we have.
See what you
can come up with.
Acknowledged.
Computer,
locate Captain Ransom.
COMPUTER:
Captain Ransom is in
crew quarters,
Deck 9, Section 22.
( ominous theme continues )
CHAKOTAY:
Chakotay to Seven of Nine.
What's your status?
I've dismantled
their antimatter injectors,
but I'll need several minutes to
neutralize the dilithium matrix.
We don't have
much time.
SEVEN:
Understood.
The Equinox crew
has been infected
with a
mutagenic virus.
It may be
contagious.
I've been authorized
to inoculate them.
You've all
contracted a virus.
I'll need
to treat you.
A virus?
Doctor's orders.
( quietly ):
It's me.
Activate
the grid.
( buzzing )
What happened?
I don't understand.
This should be
working.
I'm running a
system-wide diagnostic.
( phaser firing )
( grunting )
I'm reading phaser fire
on Deck 9, crew quarters.
Security,
seal off Deck 9.
Shields are weakening.
They're down to 84 percent.
( comlink beeps )
TUVOK: Tuvok to Bridge.
The field generator
is offline.
Its power couplings
were disengaged.
Someone reconfigured
the internal sensors
so we couldn't
detect it.
Whatever it takes,
get that grid online.
I rerouted transporter control
to a panel in the next junction.
We can--
( phaser fires )
( grunts )
( phasers firing )
( dramatic theme playing )
They've sealed off
the deck.
Don't worry.
We're getting out
of here.
Shields down
to 52 percent.
KIM:
Captain, unauthorized
transport in progress.
It's the Equinox crew.
Block it.
They've bypassed Ops Control.
They're on their Bridge.
Forty percent.
Janeway to
Seven of Nine.
JANEWAY:
Seven, respond.
Damn!
What is it?
B'Elanna's erected
a force field.
I can't get a lock
on the generator.
Try overriding
the command codes.
( console beeping )
Someone's disrupting
the force field.
It's Max.
He's using one of his
triquadric algorithms.
I taught him how to do that
10 years ago.
( dramatic theme playing )
Shields are failing. We've got
less than one minute.
Open a channel.
If you don't stop
what you're doing,
we'll both be destroyed.
What's my alternative,
30 years in your brig?
I'll open fire if I have to.
We've been through worse.
Target their power systems.
( beeps )
Fire.
Max!
Stand by!
Okay, BLT, let's see
if you remember this trick.
Bridge, they've got
the field generator.
What do you mean,
they've got it?
I don't know how,
but they beamed it off Voyager.
Get us out of here.
I can't.
Warp drive is down.
Bridge to Marla.
Report.
One of their crew tried
to dismantle
the antimatter injectors.
Repairs are underway.
What about
the field generator?
I'm integrating it
now.
( dramatic theme continues )
Shields are down.
( whirring )
Arm yourselves.
It's now or never.
Generator's in place.
I'm bringing
the grid online.
Fissures are opening,
all decks!
( whirring )
Hold your fire!
( screeching )
Take it to the lab.
( beeping )
Sir,
engines are up and running.
RANSOM:
Set a course for
the Alpha Quadrant.
BURKE:
Course laid in.
Maximum warp.
Engage.
Captain!
( screeching )
( dramatic theme continues )
( triumphant theme playing )