Last time
on  Star Trek: Voyager...
Stay the course!
They're breaking through.
We'll be dead if we don't
get the shields back up.
Arm yourselves!
( high-pitched screeching )
( screaming )
Who attacked you?
We don't know.
We can't communicate
with them.
They've been attacking
us for weeks.
Your crew has been running
criminal experiments here.
I know.
I designed them.
You?
That's a violation
of your programming.
They deleted
my ethical subroutines.
It's easy to cling to principles
when you're standing on a vessel
with its bulkheads intact,
manned by a crew
that's not starving.
It's never easy,
but if we turn our backs
on our principles,
we stop being human.
I'm putting an end
to your experiments,
and you are hereby relieved
of your command.
I rerouted transporter control
to a panel in the next junction.
We can...
Bridge, they've got
the field generator.
What do you mean,
they've got it?
I don't know how, but they
beamed it off of Voyager.
We're going home.
We can't let Voyager
stop us now,
not when we're this close.
Shields are down.
Arm yourselves.
Get us out of here.
And now the conclusion.
Fissures are opening,
all decks!
Captain!
( screeching )
( grunting )
Give me tactical control!
( alien screeching stops )
Good guess.
I used a deflector pulse
to reinforce the shields.
It won't hold for long.
PARIS: Bridge to
Sick Bay. We have
a medical emergency.
Doctor, respond.
Ensign.
Casualty reports
are coming in.
Two dead, 13 wounded.
We took heavy damage
to the engines.
The Equinox?
They've gone to warp.
Any sign of
nucleogenic particles?
No.
Then they haven't
engaged their enhanced
warp drive yet.
Keep looking for...
( eerie whirring )
Report.
The shield grid
is back in place.
The aliens are
staying clear.
Are sensors
picking up Voyager?
It looks like
they're under attack.
Maintain course.
( alarm sounding )
Captain, I found
the Doctor's mobile
emitter on Deck 9.
You might want
to take it to Sick Bay.
( groaning )
( steady tone sounds )
PARIS:
Any sign of the Doc?
I've got him right here.
Please state
the nature of the...
Don't bother.
You should start with Chakotay.
I've got him stabilized,
but he's got internal injuries.
We found your emitter
on Deck 9.
I was taken hostage
by the Equinox crew.
I deactivated
myself to escape.
Did you stop them?
No.
I'd ask for a status report,
but I'm not sure
I'd want to hear it.
Harry's analyzing the sound
we've been hearing.
He thinks it's some form
of communication.
Well, I once figured out
how to speak with
a Terrelian Seapod.
This couldn't be
that much harder.
Once I get out of Sick Bay,
I'll lend him a hand.
We should all be
focusing our efforts
on finding the Equinox.
First things first--
we've got to stop
these attacks.
JANEWAY: Our enemies
aren't the aliens.
They're the humans
aboard the Equinox.
It's crucial
that you don't...
( eerie whirring )
( door chimes )
Who is it?
It's Max.
I've brought you a visitor.
Hold on.
Come in.
I'm glad you're okay.
I've been using this
synaptic stimulator.
I was just
taking a stroll
along the
Tenkaran Coast.
You're welcome
to try it.
State your intentions.
You know, once we get
our enhanced warp drive
back on line, we'll
be on our way home.
But it'll still take
months to get there.
You can spend that time
in the brig, or...
you can become
part of this crew.
I'd prefer the latter.
I'd prefer the brig.
You know, Janeway's
not the only captain
who can help you
explore your humanity.
You would be an
inferior role model.
Janeway clung to her morality
at the expense of her crew.
Maybe you should learn
from that mistake.
Her only mistake
was trusting you.
Take care of her wound.
BURKE:
First-degree phaser burns,
minor lacerations.
Looks like we'll
have to amputate.
That was a joke.
You're supposed to smile
and make a witty retort.
I'm familiar
with human banter.
Yours is crude
and predictable.
You know, Seven--
can I call you Seven?
We don't have many
luxuries around here.
All we've got is each other.
You might try letting
your shields down,
or else it's going
to be a lonely trip.
I'll be damned.
Looks like our Doctor
left us a replacement.
Seven...?
We are captives.
I was attacked
by their EMH.
Looks like he downloaded
you into our database.
Good. You can treat
your friend.
Priming the injectors.
Marla to Bridge.
RANSOM: Go ahead.
We're ready.
Acknowledged.
Infuse the enhanced warp drive
with 20 isograms
of the compound.
Aye, sir.
Warp drive ready.
Engage.
( engine powers up shakily )
( engine dies )
What happened?
Power relays are off-line.
They've been encoded.
Give us the codes.
No.
If she won't give us
the codes, maybe we could
extract them ourselves.
Seven's cranial infrastructure
is highly complex.
You'll need months
just to figure out what
she had for breakfast.
That's why
you're gonna help us.
I refuse.
Do it or I'll
erase your program.
Be my guest.
Doctor.
Don't worry. They need me.
They'd be cutting off
their holographic nose
to spite their face.
Now, I suggest you...
RANSOM:
All right, Doctor.
Now, get to work.
You know what
we're looking for.
Very well.
She'll try to resist.
I'll have to restrain her.
Doctor.
I deleted
his ethical subroutines.
He'll be a little more
cooperative now.
You keep me posted.
Aye, Captain.
This way, please.
It's not exactly Shakespeare,
but it gets the point across.
A small olive branch
is still an olive branch.
Run this through
your translation matrix.
Set your weapons down.
Commander?
Somebody's got to start
trusting somebody around here.
Belay that order.
I appreciate your optimism,
but, in this case, weapons.
KIM:
Ready to transmit.
Drop shields,
Bridge only.
Go ahead, Harry.
( transmitting whirring tones)
( eerie whirring )
( transmission continues )
( screeching )
Raise shields.
( alien whirring stops )
If they understood our message,
they haven't responded.
There's your response.
Activate another
deflector pulse.
Shields are holding
at 62 percent.
That should buy us another
few minutes of peace and quiet.
I suggest we make
the most of it.
Focus your efforts on repairing
the warp drive.
We've got to find
the Equinox.
If it's all the same to you,
I'd like to take another
stab at the message.
If we can reroute...
They're not listening,
Chakotay.
We should be tracking Ransom,
not tinkering with adverbs.
Want your First Officer's
advice?
Allow me.
Our deflector's losing power
and when it fails,
we'll be defenseless.
It's  Voyager  we should
be worrying about,
not the Equinox.
You'd make a great
First Officer.
It's advice worth taking.
Maybe so, but we have a crew
member trapped on that ship.
Is this really about Seven,
or is it about Ransom?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You've been known
to hold a grudge.
This man betrayed Starfleet,
he broke the Prime Directive,
dishonored everything
you believe in,
and threw Voyager
to the wolves.
Borg, Hirogen, Malon--
we've run into our share
of bad guys.
Ransom's no different.
Yes, he is.
You said it yourself.
He's human.
I don't blame you
for being angry,
but you can't compromise
the safety of this ship
to satisfy some
personal vendetta.
I appreciate your candor.
Now let me be just as blunt.
You're right, I am angry.
I'm damned angry.
He's a Starfleet Captain
and he's decided
to abandon everything
this uniform stands for.
He's out there right now
torturing and murdering
innocent life-forms
just to get home
a little quicker.
I'm not going to stand for it.
I'm going to hunt him down
no matter how long it takes,
no matter what the cost.
If you want to call
that a vendetta,
go right ahead.
Why did you bring us here?
This planet has
a parthogenic
atmosphere.
It'll keep us
from being detected
while we make repairs.
We also found a few
deuterium deposits.
Take an away team, Noah,
and see if you can
localize the ore.
You won't be protected
from the aliens.
Arm yourselves
with phasers.
At the first sign of trouble,
we'll beam you back.
Aye, sir.
DOCTOR:
♪ The ocular node's connected
to the sensory node ♪
♪ The sensory node's connected
to the cortical node ♪
♪ The cortical node's connected
to the reticular node... ♪
Oh, now, don't look so gloomy.
There's a silver lining
to all this.
Just think-- we're
finally going to see Earth.
You are obviously
delusional.
Allow me to repair
your program.
Now, why would I want you
to do that?
You of all people
should understand.
Being unfettered
by ethical subroutines
has made me far more efficient.
Status?
I'm going to extract
her cortical array.
It contains an index
of her memory engrams.
But once I've removed it,
her higher brain functions,
language, cognitive skills
will be severely damaged.
Tell me the codes.
No.
Janeway was right
about one thing--
you are unique.
Now, it would be a shame
to lose you.
Your compassion
is irrelevant.
You think this
is easy for me?
The sight of you
on that table...
But you're leaving
me no choice.
"No choice."
You say that frequently.
You destroy life-forms
to attain your goals,
then claim that they
left you no choice.
Does that logic
comfort you?
The codes.
You'll have to destroy me
to obtain them.
♪ The reticular node's connected
to the occipital node... ♪
JANEWAY:
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Our warp drive's
back on line,
but repeated sensor sweeps
have failed
to locate the Equinox.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
It's not like you to submit
recommendations in writing.
The last time we spoke,
you weren't exactly receptive.
I'm afraid I'm not going to be
very receptive this time either.
It's an interesting idea,
but the Ankari
are 50 light-years
in the wrong direction.
I understand that,
but they're the ones
who introduced Ransom
to these life-forms.
It stands to reason
they might be able
to communicate with them--
tell them to call off
their attacks.
Our first priority
is to find Ransom.
Still no sign
of nucleogenic particles?
Not yet.
Then he couldn't
have gotten far.
Without his enhanced drive,
his ship's only capable
of warp 6.
I've been studying
his service record.
He's had his share of run-ins
with hostile aliens.
It seems that when
he's being pursued,
he tends to hide.
At Epsilon IV he ran into
a Klingon bird-of-prey.
Played a game of cat and mouse
for three days in a nebula
before the Klingons
finally gave up.
Two years later,
he eluded a Romulan warbird
by taking his vessel
into the atmosphere
of a gas giant.
Go to Astrometrics.
Start looking for
the kind of place
you would hide if
your ship was damaged.
Yes, ma'am.
( birds calling )
How was the beach?
Do these programs
have people in them?
No, just landscapes. Why?
Forget it.
I'm reading
a vein of ore.
Azimuth 117... 30 meters.
It could run pretty deep.
We might need to use
phasers to excavate it.
It's funny,
this reminds me
of McKinley Park.
I used to take
my sister there
when we were kids.
This place looks
just like it.
As I recall, there was
a family of ground squirrels
who lived
right over there.
And there was a patch
of poison ivy next to it.
When I was 10, I walked
right through it
and I swelled up like
a Regellian blood worm.
When I get back to Earth,
the first thing
I'm going to do is...
( grunts )
Four to beam up.
We're receiving
a subspace transmission.
From who?
I can't tell.
I don't see a ship out there.
Open a channel.
Doctor to Equinox.
Respond.
We can hear you.
Voyager's found you.
They've entered orbit.
They polarized their hull
to mask their approach.
I believe they've already
planned an ambush
on the away team.
Janeway's been tracking
the  Equinox...(static)
Get him back.
I can't.
Ransom to away team.
Noah, prepare to beam back
to the ship.
They're not down there.
All hands to battle stations.
30,000 kilometers and closing.
Target their power core.
Direct hit.
Minor damage.
Return fire.
Bridge to Torres.
Status?
I can't locate
their shield grid generator.
Can you divert more power
to sensors?
Stand by.
They've damaged
our deflector, Captain.
If it goes off-line,
we'll be vulnerable
to the alien attacks.
Noted.
Target his weapons array.
We lost our
phaser banks.
Torpedoes, full spread.
It's B'Elanna.
She's trying to bypass
our security
protocols.
Stop her.
Computer, open a com-link
to the Equinox.
Workstation 33-Beta.
Max, listen to me.
Back for round two, BLT?
This isn't one of our games.
People are dying over here.
I wish you didn't have
to be one of them.
Max, please...
Shields are weakening.
We've almost got him.
Keep targeting
their weapons array.
One more torpedo
ought to do it.
Captain...
Fire.
Weapons are down!
Janeway to Ransom.
Surrender your vessel.
We still have thrusters,
don't we?
Aye, sir.
Lay in a course
through the planet's
atmosphere--
60-degree vector.
What the hell is he doing?
Follow him.
We're crossing
the upper thermosphere.
Phasers.
( alarm sounding )
Shields are weakening--
31 percent...
29...
Inertial dampeners are off-line.
Captain, if we lose our shields,
we'll be attacked by the aliens.
( grunts )
Captain!
Break off pursuit!
They're retreating.
Take us up!
They took heavy damage--
shields, propulsion.
Get us out of here.
They've gone to warp.
Match their course
and speed.
We can't, not until we restore
primary systems.
Time?
We'll need
a few hours.
( sighs )
At least we didn't
come away empty-handed.
I want Ransom's tactical status.
I want it now, Mr. Lessing.
Or what?
You'll hit me?
No, Crewman.
I'll drop the shields
around this room,
and let your little friends
come pay you a visit.
That would be murder.
You could also call
it "poetic justice."
I suppose the plan is
that you're going to come
to my rescue now, right?
There's no plan
as far as I know.
The Captain's
on her own.
Ransom's
status, now.
No way in hell.
We all make our own hell,
Mr. Lessing.
I hope you enjoy yours.
The com is active.
We'll be outside
if you have a change of heart.
What are
you doing?
Weren't you listening?
Don't do this.
He'll break.
( eerie whirring )
Bridge to the Captain.
We've lost shields
in Section 29-Alpha.
I know. Stand by.
He's a loyal officer.
He's not going
to betray his Captain.
Put up the shields.
He'll break.
Captain!
As you were.
COMPUTER:
Level nine authorization
required.
Damn it, Kathryn!
You're panicking.
He's going to talk.
Captain, a fissure is opening
in that section.
Understood.
Okay, you've demonstrated
your loyalty to your Captain.
Fine. Now let's talk
about the Ankari.
If there's an Ankari vessel
less than two light-years
from here,
why haven't we
detected it?
Apparently, they use
a unique form of propulsion,
which makes them
hard to find.
You think they'll be
willing to help us?
It's worth a try.
Mr. Lessing has agreed
to show you how to
adjust the sensors.
Once you find
the Ankari ship,
set a course.
Aye, sir.
Did our prisoner disclose
any other information?
I'm afraid not.
The rest of you continue
with the repairs.
Dismissed.
Commander.
All right.
We're going to try
it your way.
But I want to make
one thing clear.
Our first priority
is to get Ransom.
If there's one thing
you've made clear, it's that.
We've had our
disagreements, Chakotay,
but you've never
openly opposed me.
You almost killed
that man today.
It was a calculated risk
and I took it.
It was a bad call.
I'll note your
objection in my log.
I don't give a damn
about your log.
This isn't about rules
and regulations.
It's about right and wrong.
And I'm warning you--
I won't let you
cross that line again.
Well then you
leave me no choice.
You are hereby
relieved of duty
until further notice.
What's happened
to you, Kathryn?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
They are not responding.
Tractor beam.
Captain, the Ankari ship
has done nothing to...
Just do it.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
Starfleet.
Yes.
Leave us alone.
There's nothing of value
on our ship.
We need your guidance.
Your spirits of good fortune
are attacking us.
Of course they are.
You've been killing them!
We are not the ones responsible.
Equinox.
That's right.
Can you communicate
with the aliens?
Release my ship.
I can't do that.
Not until you agree
to talk to them.
I will summon them,
but you must talk to them.
You  must convince them.
( eerie whirring )
( screeching )
They say they want
the humans to die.
A difficult place
to start a negotiation.
Will they
understand me?
Yes.
We didn't do
this to you.
We're trying to stop
the humans who did.
( screeching )
They don't believe
you would harm your own kind.
We have rules
for behavior.
The Equinox has
broken those rules
by killing your species.
It's our duty
to stop them.
( screeching )
Give us the Equinox.
Give us
the Equinox.
They insist on destroying
the ones who were responsible.
We will punish them
according to our own rules.
( screeching )
They will be
imprisoned.
They will lose
their freedom.
( screeching angrily )
All right.
If you stop
your attacks,
I'll deliver
the Equinox to you.
Captain...
I know what I'm doing, Tuvok.
These beings would destroy
Captain Ransom and his crew.
What's their answer?
Your behavior is irrational.
We could find another solution.
I've already confined
my First Officer
to quarters.
Would you like
to join him?
Well?
( screeching )
They agree.
We're going
to need more fuel.
We've only got enough
left to jump another
500 light-years.
"Fuel"? Is that
the euphemism
we're using now?
You mean we need to
kill more life-forms.
Several more.
♪ Oh, my darling,
oh, my darling ♪
♪ Oh, my darling... ♪
♪ Clementine... ♪
RANSOM:
How much longer?
Another hour.
Maybe less.
♪ You are lost
and gone forever... ♪
♪ Dreadful sorry,
Clementine... ♪
RANSOM:
What are you doing?
Hmm. Her auditory processor.
We used to practice duets
together.
In fact, I taught her
this old chestnut.
♪ Light she was ♪
♪ And like a fairy... ♪
♪ And her shoes
were number nine... ♪
♪ Herring boxes
without topses... ♪
♪ Sandals were
for Clementine... ♪
♪ Drove she ducklings
to the water... ♪
Enough.
Why the long face, Captain?
You're about to get
your crew home.
She tried to stand
in your way.
You had no choice.
No choice.
Thank you, Doctor.
When this is all over,
perhaps you'll allow me
to teach you my repertoire.
I'm going to need
a new partner.
Hmm.
♪ Drove she ducklings
to the water... ♪
You.
What are you doing here?
Hiding. Like you.
I'm not hiding.
It's beautiful.
I can see why
this brings you comfort.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
But it isn't real.
You're not real.
Now leave me alone.
It's not too late to stop.
I don't have a choice.
Find another way.
There is no other way.
Stop trying to hide.
I told you! I'm not hiding!
Now get away from me!
End this.
No!
( screeching )
BURKE:
Bridge to Ransom.
( sighs )
Go ahead.
Janeway's found us.
On my way.
Distance?
50,000 kilometers,
closing fast.
Maintain course.
Voyager's approaching
at high warp.
There's a class-2 nebula
less than a light-year
from here.
Janeway's sensors won't
be able to track us
once we're inside.
I think that we
should pursue this...
No. Open a channel.
Change of tactics?
You might say that.
It's time we found
another way home.
Another way?
We're going to cooperate
with Janeway, Max,
if she's willing.
Rudy, with all due respect,
have you lost your mind?
Just the opposite.
( console beeping )
They're within range.
They're charging weapons.
Hail them.
Belay that order.
Raise shields.
You're relieved
of duty, Commander.
I'm taking command.
Anyone who isn't
with me, speak up now.
Take him to the brig.
I'm sorry.
What's the status
of our weapons?
Full complement of torpedoes.
Minimal phasers.
Open a secure channel
to their Sick Bay.
Stand by weapons.
Aye, sir.
( console beeping )
( quietly ):
I'm here.
We going to need
your help, Doctor.
See if you can find
Voyager's current
shield frequency.
Acknowledged.
I'll need a few minutes.
They are firing torpedoes.
Direct hit to our port shields.
They're holding.
Return the favor.
This isn't the brig.
I know.
I'm with you, sir.
Let's find a way to end this.
We'll need to access
transporter control.
We've damaged
their port nacelle.
They're venting plasma.
They're dropping
out of warp.
Stay with them.
Doctor to Equinox.
I've got their shield
frequency.
I'm transmitting it
to you now.
They'll try to remodulate.
Keep monitoring.
Aye, sir.
TORRES: They've slowed to
one-quarter impulse.
Prepare a tractor beam.
They're launching
another torpedo.
Full power
to the forward shields.
( grunting )
Hull breach on Deck 4!
How'd they get
through our shields?
Hard about.
Get us out of range.
Remodulate the shields.
They're retreating.
Pursuit course.
Maintain fire.
They took out
the weapons array!
Tuvok?
I've been rotating
the shield frequency
every ten seconds.
We've lost
impulse engines.
We're being hailed.
It's Ransom.
Put him through.
Captain, I'm prepared
to surrender the Equinox,
but I'm no longer in command.
Max decided to stage
a little mutiny,
but I think I can stop him.
I've isolated
transporter control.
I can beam all of us
to Voyager.
You might want to have
some guards standing by.
Not everyone here is going
to be happy to see you.
Proceed.
Ma'am?
He's still a Starfleet Captain.
He may have forgotten that
for a while,
but I believe him.
( alarm bleeping )
Someone's trying
to beam us off.
Force fields!
They're deflecting
our targeting scanners.
Then beam the others
to Voyager,
yourself included.
I'll take
care of Max.
Aye, sir.
Computer, give me access
to the shield grid.
Well, I see you've
made yourself at home.
What are you doing here?
Taking back my Sick Bay.
Stop where you are.
I've planted photonic charges
throughout
these holo-projectors.
With one command sequence,
I can blow out your entire...
Computer, delete
the Equinox EMH.
The Doctor's not
transmitting anymore.
Burke to Doctor.
Report.
DOCTOR:
I'm afraid your physician's
no longer on call.
RANSOM:
Max, this is the Captain.
I've dropped the shield grid
everywhere except the Bridge
and my current location.
The vital systems are exposed.
I suggest you beam to Voyager
while you still can.
( screeching )
The core is overloading.
We've got to get
out of here.
Where?
Voyager's brig?
It's better
than being vaporized.
We still have
a working shuttle.
The Shuttle Bay's
two decks down!
Sir, the aliens!
We'll make it.
( eerie whirring )
This way.
( screeching )
( screaming )
( groaning )
There's only one life sign left.
It's Ransom.
Captain.
Things didn't work out
exactly as I planned,
but you've got everyone
worth getting.
We're beaming you out of there.
This ship is about to explode.
I've got to put some distance
between us.
I've accessed helm control.
You can set auto-navigation
and then transport
to Voyager.
There's no time!
You've got a fine crew, Captain.
Promise me you'll get 'em home.
I promise.
( birds calling )
Captain's Log, supplemental.
With the  Equinox  destroyed,
the aliens have withdrawn
to their realm.
I've reinstated Chakotay,
and we've set a course
for home.
Good as new.
I'd like you to regenerate
for the next few hours.
It'll help stabilize
your cortical array.
Understood.
Regarding the...
unpleasantness
aboard the Equinox,
I hope you don't
think less of me.
Your program was altered.
It's quite disconcerting
to know that all
someone has to do
is flick a switch to
turn me into Mr. Hyde.
Perhaps you should
enhance your program
with security protocols.
It will prevent such
tampering in the future.
Good thinking.
When I'm done regenerating,
I will assist you.
Thanks.
You were off-key.
I beg your pardon?
"My Darling Clementine,"
third verse, second measure.
That's impossible.
Your vocal modulations
deviated by 0.30 deci-hertz.
I can assist you
with that as well.
Really?
Holodeck 2,
tomorrow, 1600 hours.
Just you, me...
and a tuning fork.
I look forward to it.
The last time we
welcomed you aboard,
you took advantage
of our trust.
You betrayed
this crew.
I won't make
that mistake again.
Noah Lessing,
Marla Gilmore,
James Morrow, Brian
Sofin, Angelo Tassoni,
you are hereby
stripped of rank.
You'll be expected to serve
as crewmen on this vessel.
Your privileges
will be limited,
and you'll serve
under close supervision
for as long
as I deem fit.
This time, you'll
have to earn our trust.
Dismissed.
Repairs?
Coming along.
How's the crew?
A lot of frayed nerves.
Neelix is organizing
a potluck...
to help
boost morale.
Will I see you there?
I'm replicating
the salad.
I'll bring the croutons.
Chakotay...
you know...
you may have had
good reason
to stage a little mutiny
of your own.
The thought had
occurred to me,
but that would have
been crossing the line.
Will you look at that.
All these years,
all these battles.
This thing's never
fallen down before.
Let's put it back up
where it belongs.