( birds calling )
( insects chirping )
Input failure.
Our link
to the collective
has been severed.
Initiate secondary protocols.
( explosion )
The vessel's
transwarp chamber
is approaching
critical pressure.
We must evacuate this area.
ALL:
Agreed.
No directional...
ALL: coordinates are available.
That way. Bearing 301.
ALL:
Agreed.
Bring that drone.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 53049.2.
We've docked
at the Markonian Outpost
and agreed to mutual visits,
so I'm allowing shore leave
to anyone who wants it.
Commander Tuvok has objected
to taking on too many
visitors.
But, security issues aside,
I'm looking forward
to a cultural exchange
and making
some new friends.
( buzz of conversation )
Pardon me.
Excuse me.
Careful, careful.
Watch it!
Excuse me.
Captain?
I'll be right
with you.
The station manager didn't tell
me the vines were prehensile.
I went to put some water
in the pot and it grabbed me.
This is a gift
from the Kinbori Delegation.
I don't know its name,
only that it's used
in one of their sacred games
and it's very heavy.
Well, put it down anywhere.
Thank the Kinbori for me,
and give them
a token of our esteem.
I already gave them
a Voyager medallion.
They seemed appreciative.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Doesn't it
look like
Christmas morning
in here, Commander?
You have to admit
the generosity
of our guests is
very impressive.
As is their proclivity
for criminal behavior.
This morning's
security report.
Broken ODN line...
some missing personal items...
a damaged scanner relay.
All in all, not that bad.
There is a second page
to the report.
Well, some of
these incidents
are a little
more serious.
But on balance,
I still think
we did the
right thing.
There is a third page.
Come on, Tuvok,
after all the xenophobic races
we've run into
don't you find it
just a little refreshing
to meet some people
who value openness
and freedom?
Well, as far as
I'm concerned,
opening the ship has been
a fascinating experience
and an unqualified success.
I'm very pleased.
Me, too.
I am pleased
that you are pleased.
If you'll excuse me.
Tuvok...
please accept this
token of our esteem.
Oh, no.
It's got me by the hair.
Now it's 12:45.
If you're hungry,
you may eat without me.
You said we'd have
lunch together.
I haven't completed
my analysis of the station's
power conversion matrix.
How long is it
gonna take?
Several hours.
Seven, you promised.
Very well.
I think it's even more crowded
than this morning.
Yes.
Excuse us. Excuse us.
Please, we're trying to get
through to the turbolift.
Excuse us.
SEVEN:
Stand aside!
( voices fall silent )
Thank you.
I'm sorry, but there's
no more Marsupial Surprise.
We only had two kilos
of pouches to begin with
and it's all gone!
Now, how about
some pizza, huh?
She's...
a Shivolian, right?
Correct.
Species 521?
Your mother
would not approve of you
memorizing Borg designations.
I don't approve either.
We've discussed the impropriety
of you emulating the Borg.
Sorry.
I'm finished.
We just sat down.
I do not enjoy crowds.
But you were
in the collective.
Wasn't that like
a big crowd?
Which is why
I do not enjoy them now.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I didn't realize that.
Let's go.
Excuse me.
Are you Seven of Nine?
Yes.
You okay?
These are Borg synaptic relays
from my original unimatrix.
These are yours?
Where did you acquire them?
A trader from
Orendal V.
I was told you are
a former Borg drone
and might be interested
in acquiring these pieces.
I'll take them.
Captain Janeway will provide you
with whatever monetary
reimbursement you require.
Agreed.
I must examine these items
more closely.
Okay.
What's your name?
That was rude.
MALE 1:
Stage two is complete.
She has the relays.
She's going to study them.
FEMALE:
Her regeneration alcove
is in Cargo Bay 2.
MALE 2:
That's where she'll go.
We should prepare
for stage three.
Agreed.
There's consensus.
Rendezvous at my coordinates
and stand by
to penetrate their security.
Error.
Explain.
We shouldn't be desecrating
the body of this drone.
It is against the will
of Brothara.
Who is Brothara?
Brothara: a supernatural
deity worshipped
by Species 571.
I am a member of Species 571.
You're being confused
by irrelevant data.
Ignore it.
You said, "I am a
member of Species 571."
Do you consider yourself
an individual?
There are no individuals here.
We are Borg.
Agreed.
Resume constructing
the communications beacon.
It looks like
a standard Borg synaptic relay.
There must be
something more.
When I first came
into contact with it,
I was overwhelmed
with images, memories, sounds.
Sounds like a
perfectly natural
reaction to me.
That was part your
old unimatrix, right?
Well, isn't it
at least possible
that what you experienced
was simply nostalgia?
You know, sentimental
feelings about the past.
I know what nostalgia is,
but I have no feelings
about the past.
Okay. I think I've
done all I can here.
Lieutenant...
you were trying to help.
I appreciate that.
Anytime.
Oh, and, um, you may not be
nostalgic about the past,
but I'd say you definitely
have feelings about it.
Strong ones.
Their security protocols
are formidable.
We may not have
enough time.
I'm worried about
Seven of Nine.
We should reexamine
the question of
simply asking...
You know what her
reactions will be.
She won't help us
because she...
We've been
through all that.
She could be
permanently injured.
I don't want
to harm...
Enough!
We need consensus.
We can't act without it.
I know.
So, then it's up to you.
Do we proceed or not?
Yes.
We... I apologize
for my indecision.
Apologies are irrelevant!
Computer, begin
multipolar analysis.
Analysis underway.
Time to completion?
Five hours, 17 minutes.
( beeping )
She's regenerating.
Begin rerouting
their internal sensors.
Rerouting sensor input
to secondary processors.
( console beeping )
Hold.
What have you got?
There's a power fluctuation
in the security grid.
All we know is that we've
got a security breach.
We don't know where.
Ready.
Insert the interlink module.
He's still worried
about injuring her.
If we fail, we'll never
become individuals.
We have to
remember that.
There is consensus.
I've found her memory files.
She's aware
of our presence.
She's trying to
regain consciousness.
We must abort.
No! We're too close.
I will not comply.
I have performed
this action before.
I was with my father.
He was
a tall man.
I have a... similar memory.
But I was in a house
and the fire was in a hearth.
The biomatter
is ready.
It tastes similar
to a bird I once ate.
I used to prepare food...
for...
my parents.
They lived...
in a small building
by...
a river.
I used to be...
afraid of the dark.
Just before I was assimilated,
I was...
eating with a group of men.
We... worked in numbers.
Mathematics.
I... calculated equations
for another man.
I have a name.
It's...
Marika.
Marika Willkarah.
Willkarah.
Hello, Marika Willkarah.
Her designation
is Three of Nine.
MALE 2:
I have a name.
P'Chan.
Son of Dornar and Ansha.
My primary function
was to care for them.
FEMALE: I was married.
We were on a starship...
the Excalibur.
I worked
in Engineering.
This is not my hand.
MALE 2:
My parents... they're dead.
The Borg killed them.
I hate the Borg.
This is counterproductive.
We must delete
all irrelevant data.
I want my hand back.
I was on duty...
the night watch...
when the Borg came....
Oh, my God!
Look at what they've...
done to me!
These-these things
they put in my body!
What have they done?
Command override.
Cease this interaction!
Comply.
We will not access
these memory files again.
Initiate the prescribed
maintenance and survival
protocols only.
No further communication
is required,
until we are reassimilated
into the collective.
Agreed.
...but whoever removed their
implants was a poor surgeon.
Their internal organs were
damaged during the procedure
and their bodies are
covered with scars.
You said you recognized them.
Not at first.
But when they attempted
to access my memory files,
I was momentarily linked
with them.
Two of Nine.
Three of Nine.
Four of Nine.
We were all members
of the same unimatrix.
Do you know why they were trying
to access your memories?
No.
How long have they
been disconnected
from the collective?
Three or
four months.
However, they are still
connected to each other.
Somehow, the left parietal
lobes of their brains
have been transformed
into organic interlink nodes.
They've become
linked together
into a sort of
collective triad.
Revive them.
I'm Captain Janeway.
We know who you are,
and we know
what you were trying to do.
What we don't know is why.
She has
information
we need.
What kind of information?
We want to become...
Individuals.
You want to break
the neural link
between the three
of you?
Wouldn't you?
None of us is alone
with our own thoughts,
our own feelings.
Every day of my
life is spent
hearing their two
voices in my head.
When we're asleep, we experience
each other's dreams.
How's that different
from life in the collective?
In the collective, there
are billions of voices.
They become... white noise.
But with only
three...
Each voice comes through
clearly.
It has to stop.
We must break
the neural link.
Doctor, is there anything
you can do?
The modifications
are too extensive.
Their neuronal pathways
have been fundamentally
altered.
You hold the key.
Why?
You were there with us.
Planet 1865 Alpha.
You must remember.
Eight years ago,
our vessel crashed.
The four of us were
the only survivors.
When we were
reassimilated...
We found we'd been linked
together somehow.
We were a subset
within the collective.
It's like having
three voices whispering
in one ear...
And a crowd screaming
in the other.
We had to break free,
so we worked together,
and we finally
escaped.
We had our implants
removed on Inavar Prime.
But they couldn't break
the neural link.
We need to find out
what happened
eight years ago
after the crash...
The night we were
reassimilated
into the collective.
We need to know how
the link was created.
But our memories
are...
Fragmented, disorganized.
We hoped
that you would know.
I don't.
However, I am willing to attempt
to retrieve the data.
Come with me.
Are you ready?
Yes.
Data search complete.
Do you remember
anything further?
No.
My last memory is of us...
Is of us standing around...
Around a
campfire.
And yet the data files
in your cortical processor
appear to be intact.
I see no evidence
that would explain
your lapse in memory.
What about you?
Why don't you remember
what happened?
I don't know.
I've found no evidence
of damage to my
memory files either.
I remember the campfire
and then waking up
in the collective.
There is an obvious gap...
but no indication of why.
Why do they still
call you Seven?
You should have a name.
It is my name.
No.
It's a designation.
You're an individual now.
I decided that my former name
was no longer appropriate.
Prepare to reinitialize
the memory cascade.
I can't wait to use
my real name again.
There is nothing
preventing you
from doing so.
Except that
most of the time,
I don't know whether my name
is Marika, P'Chan or Lansor.
The names,
the memories...
The memories,
even the thoughts
flow from one
to the other.
I can't love
or hate or laugh...
Or cry without...
or cry without...
sharing it with them.
How can any of us take
a name for ourselves...
For ourselves?
We're not individuals.
We're not Borg.
We're nothing.
Begin the memory cascade.
JANEWAY:
"A friendly game"?
Well... that's how it started.
JANEWAY:
I see. And perhaps you
could explain to me
how this friendly game
turned into a street brawl?
( clears throat ):
Well, Harry and I
wanted to explore
the station.
Um... we wanted
to broaden
our understanding
of alien cultures and, uh...
Skip the recruiting
speech.
You were looking
for a bar. Then what?
Well, we found one
and we met a pair
of Kinbori who told us
about this game they play
with these big,
odd-looking rackets...
You mean one of those?
BOTH:
Yeah!
I-in any case,
they challenged us
to a game
and we accepted,
but I guess we weren't quite
aware of all the rules.
Because you'd been drinking.
Yes, ma'am.
Y-You see, we thought
it was a version
of tennis,
but as soon as we hit
the first volley,
this Kinbori jumps
over the net
and starts attacking
us with his racket.
So we figured we were
supposed to fight back...
Yeah.
And then, uh...
well, things got
a little out of hand.
"A little out of hand."
Seven Voyager crewmen,
including two Bridge officers,
along with 13 Kinbori
and one Morphinian cafe owner...
all arrested.
The charges range
from disorderly conduct
to assault
on a security officer.
Th-That one's not true.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Kim.
I'll note that exception
in my log.
You're both confined to quarters
until further notice--
after you report to Sick Bay.
That's all.
Well, did you win?
Oh, yes, ma'am.
We kicked their... rackets.
Good. Dismissed.
Any progress?
I've determined that we all
have exactly the same gap
in our memories.
It seems unlikely
that it would be a coincidence.
So you believe
the collective
deliberately wiped
your recollections
of the reassimilation process?
It is the most
likely explanation.
But...?
The collective
would not care
that four drones remembered
being reassimilated.
Something must have happened
during the process.
Something they wanted
to hide from you.
Let's look at this from
a different perspective.
Why would the collective
lock them into a neural
triad in the first place?
I don't know.
There is no advantage
to having three drones
linked together
in this manner.
Well, they obviously did
it for some reason...
and I get the feeling
that if we can answer
that question, the rest
should fall into place.
But I wish we
could find a way
to close the gaps
in your memories.
There is a way.
I assume there's
a reason
you didn't mention
it before now.
It would involve linking
my neural interface to theirs.
Together, we may be able
to restore the missing data.
However, I would again
be part of a group mind.
You're not eager
to revisit
that experience, hmm?
There's also the possibility
that I could become trapped
in the neural link.
Turning the triad
into a quartet.
I won't ask you to
take that kind of risk.
I do feel compelled
to help them,
but I am uncertain as to
the correct course of action.
Let me ask you something.
Do you think of these
people... as family?
Is it relevant?
There's an old saying:
"Blood is thicker
than water."
It means that
the ties of family
run deeper than any other
kind of relationship.
We'll often do things
for members of our family
we'd never dream of
doing for anyone else.
Seven!
Naomi Wildman.
I heard about the drones.
Did they hurt you?
I am not damaged.
What do they want?
They are seeking
information from me,
but I am uncertain
whether I can help them.
Oh. Be careful.
Naomi Wildman,
do you consider me to be family?
I... I don't, I mean...
well...
yes.
Is... that okay?
I have no objection.
Do you...
think of me as family?
Yes.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
Seven of Nine has decided
to undergo the procedure
that will link her mind
with the other drones.
Despite the risk involved,
she feels an obligation
to help these
"distant cousins."
I'll be monitoring
your neural readings
while you're in the link.
But I'm not certain
I'll be able to counter
the effects if...
you become trapped.
I know you'll
do your best.
It's never a good sign
when the patient
feels the need
to comfort the doctor.
Good luck.
Ready.
( groans )
( distant,
jangling beeping )
( beeping continues )
You are damaged.
I will assist you.
( softer ):
Don't worry.
Everything will be all right.
( groaning )
The collective
has located us.
A Borg vessel
is on its way.
We will be one
with the Borg again.
No! I do not want
to rejoin the collective.
Agreed.
That is in violation of
all established protocols.
Forget the protocols.
You're not a drone.
You're a person, like us.
You have a name... a life!
All you have to do is embrace
who you really are.
No. I do not exist.
I am only part
of the greater whole.
That's what they
want you to believe.
That's what they want
us all to believe.
We are Borg.
Our primary function
is to serve the collective.
Not anymore.
Error! Input failure!
They may know what planet we're
on, but without the beacon,
it'll be far more difficult
to locate us.
If we can remodulate
our cortical implants,
we might be able
to elude their sensors.
TWO OF NINE:
We must leave
this place.
This discussion
is in violation
of all established
protocols.
You stay here
and be reassimilated
if you want to.
I won't!
( groaning )
( moans )
What are you... doing?
The nanoprobes will
create new interlink nodes
in your left hemisphere.
Resistance is futile.
( panting )
I will not comply!
( moans )
State your designations.
Two of Nine,
Primary Adjunct
of Unimatrix 01.
Three of Nine,
Auxiliary Processor
of Unimatrix 01.
Four of Nine,
Secondary Adjunct
of Unimatrix 01.
What is your primary function?
ALL:
To serve the collective.
You will repair
the communications beacon.
TWO OF NINE: It was you!
You were responsible.
What have you done to us?
You linked us together.
You're responsible
for our suffering.
How could you do it?
If you didn't want
to return...
To the collective...
You didn't have to.
You don't understand
what happened.
( all talking )
Somebody help me!
( all yelling )
What's happening?
Somehow, they broke
their link with Seven.
They're malfunctioning.
Help me get them
to Sick Bay.
( yelling continues )
When they broke
the connection with you,
it must have overloaded
their cortical implants.
They went into neural shock.
And yet I was
undamaged.
I think I know why.
You said you remembered
injecting them
with nanoprobes
eight years ago...
Yes.
It created an interlink
between them.
It was the only way
to prevent them from
escaping the collective.
Well, it seems to have had
an unfortunate side effect.
Their higher brain functions
were somehow tied
into the interlink.
When they broke their connection
with you in the Cargo Bay,
the shock to their cognitive
systems was too great.
Can you revive them?
I could remove
the microcortical implants.
That would break the link
binding them together,
but it would also kill them.
They'd only live
a matter of weeks.
A month at the most.
What are the other options?
They could be returned
to the Borg.
If they were reassimilated
into the collective, they
would regain consciousness
and then live out
a normal life span.
As drones.
As drones,
but they'd be alive, Seven.
They have no hope of surviving
unless they return
to the collective.
Not exactly
a happy ending, is it?
No.
Back on that planet...
why do you think
you reacted so differently
from the rest of them?
Why were you so afraid
of becoming an individual?
When I was first assimilated
into the collective,
I was a child.
They were assimilated
as adults.
When our individual memories
began to resurface...
Yours were of being
a little girl...
a scared little girl.
I let that fear control me.
After I saw the drone
die in the swamp,
I... panicked.
I began to envision
my own death...
alone...
without even the sound of
another drone to comfort me.
So I forced them to return.
I infiltrated their left
cerebral hemispheres
with nanoprobes and created
a new interlink network--
one that they
couldn't resist.
And then I eliminated
the evidence of
what I'd done.
You were overwhelmed
by feelings you couldn't
begin to understand.
You're not responsible
for that.
Because of what I did,
they'll be forced to live
the rest of their lives
in the collective.
For that, I am responsible.
There's a difference
between surviving and living.
They'll survive
in the collective,
but they won't really be alive.
You know that better
than any of us.
There is no alternative.
How long would they survive
if the Doctor
deactivated this...
interlink network
you created?
A month at most.
A month as an individual
or a lifetime as a drone.
Which option would you choose?
Survival is insufficient.
I beg your pardon?
Eight years ago, I forced them
to return to the collective.
I won't make
the same mistake again.
They deserve to exist
as individuals.
We must terminate the link
between them.
I understand that you feel
a certain responsibility
for these patients.
But as their physician,
so do I.
It's my duty to preserve
their lives for as long as
possible, even if that means...
I will not return them
to the Borg.
Are you thinking of what's best
for them... or for you?
Clarify.
You said it yourself.
You made a mistake.
And Seven of Nine doesn't like
to make mistakes.
She strives
for perfection.
I want you to think about the
motivation behind your decision.
Are you doing what's right
for those three people...
or are you trying to alleviate
the guilt you feel
over what happened
eight years ago?
The damage I did
can never be repaired,
and my guilt is irrelevant.
I simply want them to experience
individuality... as I have.
As you have.
At one time,
you were confined
to this Sick Bay.
Your program was limited to
emergency medical protocols.
In some ways, you were not
unlike a drone.
But you were granted
the opportunity to explore
your individuality.
You were allowed to
expand your program.
Your mobile emitter gives
you freedom of movement.
Your thoughts are your own.
If you were told
you had to become
a drone again,
I believe you
would resist.
( softly ):
Yes, I suppose I would.
They would resist as well.
They would choose freedom,
no matter how fleeting.
Only you and I can truly
understand that.
Survival is insufficient.
It's so... quiet.
I had no idea
you were going to say that.
I don't know what
either of you is thinking.
I'd forgotten
what it was like
to be alone with
my own thoughts.
I'm leaving.
Where will you go?
I want to see the space station.
To meet new people.
To fill my life...
with life again...
in the time I have left.
I'm leaving as well.
There's an uninhabited planet
only a few light-years
from here.
I'd like to spend
my final days
in the open air.
My people don't believe
in holding grudges.
I wish you well,
Seven of Nine.
Thank you.
It's nice to be on a
Federation starship again.
I'd like to stay
aboard Voyager.
The Captain said you may
stay as long as you wish.
You mean as long as I have.
I can't forgive you
for what you did to us.
But I do understand
why you did it.
Naomi Wildman.
I thought you might
like some company.
Why?
Because of... what
happened with the drones.
I see that word travels quickly.
It's a small ship.
I thought maybe you might want
to spend some time with...
family.