Torres to Voyager.
I could use a little help here.
CHAKOTAY:
What's your status?
I'm approaching your position,
but that ion storm
blew out my deflector field.
I've lost helm control,
and I'm venting plasma
from the port nacelle.
We're modifying a tractor pulse
to slow you down.
Acknowledged.
The arresting fields
are in place.
You're clear to land.
JANEWAY:
Hold on, B'Elanna.
This is going to be bumpy.
( grunts )
B'Elanna?
Oh.
Are you alive?
You tell me.
You've got
a mild concussion.
That's the best thing
that's happened
to me all day.
When I give you an order,
I expect you to follow it.
I told you to
return to Voyager,
not chase the probe
into the center
of an ion storm.
We only have one
multispatial probe.
I didn't want to lose it.
We only have
one B'Elanna Torres.
I don't want to lose her,
either.
Understood.
Lanna.
I'm glad you made it back
in one piece.
Did you just call me "Lanna"?
I suppose I did.
That's what my mother
used to call me.
Well, then, I'm in good company.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Feeling better?
I've felt worse.
I found something you might
be interested in.
It's what my ancestors called
a "monkey wrench."
It was lodged
in your port nacelle.
How did it get there?
Judging by your sensor logs,
it looks like you ran into it
after your deflector field
collapsed.
But the big question is:
How did it get in this quadrant?
What do you mean?
What?
It's Klingon.
And it's old.
That's about all we know.
Looks like the Klingons beat
Starfleet to the Delta Quadrant
by a few hundred years.
You may be holding the most
important archaeological find
in Klingon history.
Remind me to plant a flag
on behalf of the Empire.
You know,
the simplest explanation
is that the Borg assimilated
a bird-of-prey
somewhere in
the Alpha Quadrant,
and they blew it out an
airlock on their way home.
Maybe so.
In any case, it makes
a nice souvenir.
( distant yelling )
( cacophony of
Klingon voices)
( voices stop )
Harry, it bled, it screamed.
There's got to be
some explanation.
Hey, I've got
one for you.
You hit your head harder
than you thought.
I wasn't hallucinating.
Now, run a submolecular scan.
How many more scans
are we going to run?
There is nothing there.
No fluid or vapor residue.
We may find some irregularities
at the atomic level.
It's a hunk of metal.
What you heard
may have had nothing to do
with this artifact.
Maybe the com system
picked up some stray signal
from a pulsar--
I don't know.
A pulsar that speaks Klingon.
( chuckles ):
Okay, B'Elanna, there
probably is some explanation
for what happened,
but it's 0300 hours.
I'm tired, you're tired.
Let's just stick
this thing in a
containment field
and deal with it
in the morning.
NEELIX:
Ah! Just the daughter
of the Empire
I've been looking for.
I wanted to be the first
to congratulate you
on your discovery
of the Klingon artifact.
Neelix, I ran into it
with a shuttle.
Some of the greatest discoveries
in Klingon history
were accidents.
When Sarpek the Fearless
unearthed the Knife of Kiromm
he was searching
for his lost targ.
( laughing ):
Isn't that amazing?
I've been doing
some research.
Why?
Well, I'm planning
a celebration.
This... must be
the treasure.
Neelix, look, I appreciate
your enthusiasm,
but since I'm the only Klingon
onboard, there's really no point
in throwing a party.
Oh, nonsense.
This artifact isn't just
a testament to Klingon spirit.
It's a piece
of the Alpha Quadrant--
a symbol
of Voyager's home,
and that's just as worthy
of celebration and song
as finding some old knife.
Man's got
a point.
Besides, I've already
replicated five barrels
of bloodwine.
I'm not going to let them
go to waste.
Festivities begin
at 1900 hours.
Oh! Uh, I
almost forgot.
As guest of honor,
you're gonna be expected
to say a few words
on behalf of your people.
Sounds like you got
a big day ahead of you.
You should probably
get some rest.
All right, all right,
let's call it a night.
Thank you.
TUVOK:
Do not underestimate
the power of the mind.
The artifact was a catalyst for
your already active imagination.
It served as an unwelcome
reminder of your ancestry--
the self-loathing you experience
when you look in the mirror
and see a Klingon.
Who said anything
about self-loathing?
You despise being Klingon.
It's no secret.
What you experienced
in your quarters
was a subconscious manifestation
of that hatred.
The blood in your veins,
the voices
of your ancestors--
all symbols of
your Klingon heritage.
And when the blood
disappeared,
that was, what?
Me trying to vaporize
that part of myself?
Yes. But the essence of
who you are-- the artifact
itself-- remained.
And the moral
of the story is...?
Quite simple.
That despite your efforts
to become something else,
whether it be Starfleet
or Maquis,
your Klingon nature
continues to assert itself.
That's an intriguing theory.
Perhaps we should forego
your meditation
in favor of
a different exercise.
Fine by me.
This should be
interesting.
Feel the weight of
the bat'leth in your hands.
Describe the first thought
that enters your mind.
It's a clumsy weapon,
overstated,
like everything
else Klingon.
You can't see the elegance
of its design,
because of your hatred.
I don't hate Klingons.
It's a warrior's blade...
crafted for precision
and balance.
Observe.
Is this your idea of therapy?!
Listen to yourself whine
like a Ferengi.
pahtk!
You're not worthy of
the blood in your veins.
A true Klingon would try
to kill me where I stand.
What the hell has
gotten into you?
This exercise is over.
You are dismissed,
Lieutenant,
and take your dishonor
with you.
DOCTOR:
♪ ...migh hohk-chew koo ♪
♪ Ej IM-ta fe DE-ja i... ♪
And the blood
was ankle-deep.
♪ ejdahk-so-TAS ghos
va Skral byteek... ♪
And the river Skral
ran crimson red.
I fail to see the merit
of learning a Klingon
drinking song.
It's not about
drinking, Seven.
It's about saluting the noble
deeds of our ancestors
and honoring those
who fell in battle.
Think "Qapla'!"
Think "Long live
the Empire!"
SEVEN:
Think again.
DOCTOR:
Okay, so I'm
overdoing it a bit,
but try to get into the
spirit of the occasion.
Very well.
♪ Ej IM-ta fey ♪
BOTH:
♪ DE-ja i ♪
♪ ejdahk-so-TAS
ghos va Skral byteek ♪
♪ Empa jaj law-moch jaj-pusH ♪
♪ jaj Kahless Molor-migh
hohk-chew koo. ♪
( applause )
gagh, anyone?
Sop joq jiH yuv gagh drek!
He said, "Eat this
or he'll force it down
the gullet of your corpse."
No offense.
Oh, none taken.
So this is replicated,
right?
Unfortunately.
And how do you get it to...
move?
I used a kinesthetic agent
to give it a little oomph.
Is it just me,
or has everyone
gone Klingon-happy?
Oh, come on, B'Elanna.
They're all doing this
for you.
Well, then they don't
know me very well.
And if you even think
of joining in
on this "embrace your heritage"
nonsense,
I swear I'll rip out your tongue
and wear it as a belt.
Oh, no... there's not
a lot of Klingon in you.
I inherited the forehead and
the bad attitude-- that's it.
( laughter )
She would have
loved all this.
Your mother?
She was so obsessed
with Klingon ritual, myths.
It used to drive
my father and me crazy.
Did I ever tell you that she
put me in a Klingon monastery?
Ah. You're kidding.
It was after their
marriage ended.
She pulled me out of
the Federation school
in order to teach me...
honor and discipline.
Hmm... out of the plasma cooker
into the fire.
She prayed to Kahless every day
to guide me in the ways
of the warrior.
I guess he wasn't listening.
( tapping )
Ladies and gentlemen,
could I have
your attention, please?
I hate to interrupt
the festivities,
but before I turn the floor
over to our resident Klingon,
I'd like to say
a few words.
This is a great day
for the Klingon Empire--
a day when we honor
their ancestors.
( slowing and echoing ):
Those warriors whose deeds
of valor and glory...
( echoing and fading ):
led them to the Delta Quadrant.
( slow and distorted ):
May they live on
in song and story.
( heartbeat thumping )
( Janeway continues
indistinctly )
( heartbeat thumping )
( indistinct )
Captain!
( yelling and grunting )
( groans )
legh soH va Gre'thor!
( growls )
( yelling )
( thunder cracks )
Where am I?
Silence.
The dead ask no questions.
( thunder rumbles )
( grunting )
Computer, end program!
Qem nuH meq!
Let go of me!
( thunder cracks )
( gasps )
Wait... wait...
'uch ghaH.
Uh, wait...
( grunts )
( yelling in pain )
( growling )
( gasping )
She won't take the mark.
What the hell is going on?
Qusdaq. ba'daH.
( grunts )
mag hoshonaH nes'a.
Where am I?
You should know;
you're half Klingon.
Enlighten me.
This is the Barge
of the Dead.
Our dishonored souls are
being taken to Gre'thor.
Klingon hell is a myth.
That's what I thought--
just a foolish superstition.
Imagine my surprise.
But I was on Voyager
with my crew.
That was the naj--
the dream before dying.
When we can't accept
that we've died,
we create the illusion of life
to hold on to.
( Klingon voices )
He slaughtered my friends.
No. He slaughtered
the dream.
He dragged you
from the illusion of life.
This is where you belong.
( distant clamoring voices )
What is that?
It's the kos'kari.
They'll try to lure you to them.
Don't listen.
( clamoring voices
continue )
CHAKOTAY ( distantly):
B'Elanna, are you there?
JANEWAY:
Lieutenant, can you hear me?
PARIS:
Help us find you!
TORRES:
Tom? Chakotay?
It's not
your friends!
jiH qoy soH!
( splashing )
( screaming )
( creatures squealing )
There are things here
worse than death.
You.
Is this the mongrel
child you spoke of?
Yes. The one whose face
would not bear the mark.
B'Elanna, daughter of Miral...
it's not your time.
How do you know my name?
You've come close
to boarding this ship
many times.
I remember the first.
You were a child.
Your mother took you
to the Sea of Gatan.
Your curiosity was
as deep as the water.
I fell in.
I almost drowned.
When your mother breathed life
back into your lungs
she told you about me.
So you're supposed to be Kortar.
Ah... you remember me.
I remember
the myth of Kortar,
the first Klingon.
He destroyed the gods
who created him.
And as punishment,
I was condemned to ferry
the souls of the dishonored
to Gre'thor.
I may have believed in you
as a child, but not anymore.
If you didn't
still believe,
you wouldn't be here.
( chuckling )
Foolish girl.
( grunts )
You cannot harm me.
I'm already dead.
( grunts )
What's happening?
The soul of another
dishonored warrior
is being delivered.
kot'mah soH
Gre'thor!
Qapla.
Mother.
( chuckling )
( grunts )
It's all right.
You're safe.
Your shuttle was drifting
on the trailing edge
of an ion storm.
You lost life support.
We found you just in time.
But I got
through the storm.
I remember crashing
into the Shuttle Bay.
When we tractored
your shuttle
back to Voyager,
you were in a coma.
We almost lost you.
The Klingon artifact...
Artifact?
My hand...
You took quite
a beating out there--
more than your fair share
of cuts and bruises.
( door chimes )
Come in.
How are you feeling?
Um... a little out of place.
Would you like to talk about it?
Yes...
and no.
Let me know when you decide.
I don't know
how to say this
without sounding crazy.
Try.
Do you believe
in an afterlife?
I accept there are
things in the universe
than can't be scanned
with a tricorder.
What happened
to you out there?
I think...
I died.
I died, and I was on
the Barge of the Dead,
in the Klingon afterlife.
Klingon mythology has
been ingrained in you
since you were a child.
It's not surprising
you experienced
some of those images
while you were unconscious.
I saw my mother, Chakotay.
If it was real, then she's dead.
B'Elanna...
your mother...
the Barge of the Dead...
these are just symbols.
It's your subconscious mind
trying to tell you something.
Tell me what?
That my mother is going to hell?
You need time
to digest what you experienced.
You have to interpret
the symbols
and search
for their meaning.
What if there is no symbolism
to interpret?
What if the afterlife is real?
I'm an engineer.
My whole life,
I've immersed myself
in science and...
and schematics.
But what if it's time
to start looking beyond that?
My grandfather used to...
think he could transform himself
into a wolf,
so that he could venture out
to explore the spirit realm.
It was real to him.
As real as what you experienced
was to you,
but that doesn't mean
he grew hair all over his body
and walked around
on all fours.
My mother has been
on my mind a lot lately.
We just had a big anniversary.
It's been ten years...
since we talked.
But it was so real.
I could taste the blood
in the air.
I could feel the wind.
I was seasick
from the rocking of the boat.
( sighs )
Hi.
What are you reading?
The paq'batlh.
It's a sacred
Klingon scroll.
Find anything?
You don't want to know.
Oh, come on.
It can't be that bad.
You want to bet?
I found out
why my mother
is on her way
to Gre'thor.
It's because
I sent her there.
What do you mean?
The sins of the child.
She's being punished
for my dishonor.
I turned my back
on everything Klingon,
and now she has
to pay the price.
B'Elanna, you
can't even be sure
your mother is dead,
much less blame yourself
for what happens to her
in some afterlife.
Look at this.
The Eleventh Tome of Klavek.
It's a story about
Kahless returning
from the dead...
"still bearing a wound
from the afterlife"--
a warning that what
he experienced wasn't a dream.
The same thing
happened to me.
B'Elanna, this...
And the only reason
Kahless was in the afterlife
to begin with
was to rescue his brother
from the Barge of the Dead
and deliver him
to Sto-Vo-Kor.
Okay.
Don't you see?
I have a chance
to rescue my mother
if I can accept responsibility
for her dishonor
before she passes through
the gates of Gre'thor.
I have to go back.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
What do you mean,
"go back"?
I can't let her suffer
for what I've done.
It's the only way.
B'Elanna, I respect
what you believe in,
but you're starting
to scare me.
I'm scaring myself.
TORRES:
It's a controlled
procedure.
I'll be under
constant supervision.
The Doctor can simulate
the conditions of the ion storm.
He's agreed to help me,
but only with your permission.
I'm still not inclined
to grant your request.
Are you telling me
that I can't pursue
my spiritual beliefs?
B'Elanna, I'm not
going to let you
turn this into a debate
about freedom of worship.
But that's what it is.
There's a limit to how far
I'll let religious practices go
aboard this ship.
If your belief system
required you to sacrifice
a child to your gods,
I wouldn't
allow that, either.
That's an absurd example.
You want to simulate
a near-death experience,
so you can revisit
the Barge of Death,
and you're telling me
what's absurd?
Bottom line, B'Elanna--
I'm not going to let you
risk your life for this.
Captain, please.
Request denied.
What I do with my own life
is one thing,
but to know that I have
condemned my mother...
that because of what I've done,
she's...
I appreciate what you're
trying to say, B'Elanna,
but whatever you experienced,
it wasn't real.
It doesn't matter
if you think it was real.
It was real to me.
Whatever it was, it changed me.
I can't ignore that.
I need to confront
what's happened.
I'm sorry.
You know, you're just like her.
Lieutenant?
My mother.
You're as dedicated
to Starfleet principles
as she was to
Klingon honor.
I know that we haven't
always seen eye to eye,
but despite our differences,
you helped me
become a good officer
and I'd like to think
that you're proud of me for it.
I am.
My mother never had the chance
to be proud of me.
I'd like her to know me
the way you do.
I don't want her to die
thinking of me as a disgrace.
You have
to let me do this.
I can't believe
the Captain
is allowing this.
One minute,
you're in a coma.
The next, you're
a born-again Klingon?
I-I just don't get it.
I'm not sure
I get it, either.
I just know this is something
I have to do.
There's got to be
an easier way
for you to explore
your spirituality.
Go to church, or something?
It wouldn't be enough.
Look, I'll read
the scrolls.
I'll learn Klingon.
We'll figure this out...
together.
Next time.
I just hope
there is a next time.
There will be.
Report.
I've examined
the sensor logs from
the shuttle mission.
I should be able to re-create
the exact conditions
that triggered
her near-death experience.
Good. B'Elanna?
I'm ready.
Be careful.
You'll have an hour to do
whatever it is you need to do.
At the first sign of trouble,
we're bringing you out.
Understood?
Computer...
erect an isolation field
around the Surgical Bay.
Decrease oxygen concentration
within the force field
by 27 percent.
Begin ionizing
the enclosed atmosphere
to 5,000 particles
per cubic meter.
She's unconscious.
PARIS: Neural activity
is decreasing to 87 percent...
62 percent...
( alarm beeping )
Synaptic function
is failing.
Compensating.
( console beeping )
Neural activity
is nominal.
She's not breathing.
She's still alive.
Her lungs are taking in
just enough oxygen
to keep her brain
from necrotizing.
Qapla', B'Elanna.
(thunder cracks )
KLINGON:
suS'ag Gre'thor qay.
( thunder cracks )
Mother.
Stay away.
You are an illusion.
You're a kos'kari
trying to lure me away.
Mother, it's me.
It's me.
B'Elanna?
No.
Then you died as well?
I've come to lift
your dishonor.
But you don't believe
in Sto-Vo-Kor.
A lot's happened since
the last time I saw you.
I've changed.
Not enough.
It was you who brought
this damnation upon me.
If you hadn't
tried to, to force me
to become a warrior...
I tried to guide you
in the ways of a Klingon.
You tried a
little too hard.
If you had listened to me
when you were younger,
we wouldn't be on
the Barge of the Dead.
You were always running away.
You drove me away...
the same way you
drove away my father.
He abandoned us.
You pushed him to the point
where he couldn't bear
to be around anything
Klingon... including me.
I wanted to give you honor.
And if you had
understood that,
I would not be
on my way to Gre'thor.
We're on the Barge
of the Dead...
and we're still having
the same argument
we were having
ten years ago.
( scoffs )
Look, if I have
dishonored you,
I am truly sorry.
Are you?
You have too much anger
in your heart to be sorry.
Oh, we don't have
time for this
if we're going
to perform the
transference.
Is that how you intend
to lift my dishonor?
By taking my place?
Oh, don't worry.
I have no intention
of being on this barge
when it gets
to Gre'thor.
We've got just enough time
to perform the ritual
before my crew
resuscitates me.
Oh.
I should have known
you'd choose the easy way.
What are you talking about?
Do you know the risks
I've taken to save you?
You still understand nothing
about being a Klingon.
I would rather face damnation
with what little honor
you have left me
than cheat my way
into Sto-Vo-Kor.
( footsteps approaching )
There she is.
Bring them.
The mongrel child
has returned.
I'm here to take
my mother's place.
B'Elanna!
You wish to claim
her dishonor as your own?
Yes.
You're willing
to die for her?
Yes. Release her
to Sto-Vo-Kor.
No!
Keep her quiet!
Silence!
It's not your decision.
She has the right
to reclaim your honor.
Once we have
reached Gre'thor
and you are
within its gates,
I will release her.
No. Now.
( chuckles )
You're very impatient.
Time must be slipping away
in the living world.
You're concerned that
your friends will revive you
before you complete
your deception.
Did you really think
I could be fooled so easily?
( muffled protest )
I will die for her.
No tricks,
no games.
I will take her place honorably.
Like a Klingon.
KORTAR:
If you choose this path,
your friends
will not be able to save you.
No! I forbid it!
I understand.
Your dishonor has been lifted.
Sto-Vo-Kor awaits you.
I will not abandon my daughter.
She has made the choice. Go!
Daughter of Miral,
embrace your fate.
Vih.
Her neural patterns
are breaking down.
I'm initiating
emergency resuscitation.
Vent the ionized
particles.
20 milligrams
cordrazine now!
I'm deactivating
the force field.
( alarm beeping )
( grunts )
Welcome to Gre'thor.
This isn't Gre'thor.
Oh, I assure you it is.
You've taken your mark.
What is this,
some kind of a joke?
This is no laughing matter.
You've met Mr. Neelix,
our Ambassador to
the recently deceased.
Questions, comments,
suggestions... he's your man.
If you'll follow me.
By the way,
I'll be performing an aria
from Berlioz's Faust
tomorrow night in Holodeck 2.
Feel free to stop by.
15 decks.
Computers augmented
with bio-neural circuitry.
Top cruising speed:
warp 9.975.
Not that you'll
be going anywhere.
No Fek'lhr?
No Cavern of Despair?
Don't need them.
I don't consider
Voyager hell!
Are you sure?
Have you ever been
truly happy here?
If you thought 50 years
aboard this ship
would be difficult,
try eternity.
ALL:
♪ Ej IM-ta fey DE-ja i ♪
♪ ejdahk-so-TAS
ghos va Skral byteek ♪
♪ Empa jaj law-mooch
jaj-pusH... ♪
( tapping )
This is a great day
for B'Elanna Torres,
a day when we pay tribute
to her dishonor.
DOCTOR:
She's not responding
to the cordrazine.
Neural activity
at 48 percent... 37.
We're losing her.
We have to stabilize
her synaptic functions.
I'm attempting
a direct neural resequencing.
B'Elanna's misdeeds
have led her to Gre'thor.
She comes with no valor,
no glory...
nothing to celebrate
in song and story.
You really have no one
to blame but yourself.
You've kept us all
at arm's length,
even Tom,
who you claim to love.
Hear, hear.
I tried to assist you
in making Engineering
more efficient,
but you resisted.
You're stubborn.
She inherited that from her
mother along with the forehead.
CHAKOTAY:
What do you think
of the afterlife so far?
It's not exactly
what I had in mind.
Are you interpreting
all the symbols?
Searching your subconscious
for their meaning?
TUVOK:
Lieutenant Torres...
defend yourself.
( thunder cracks )
Captain?
What are you still doing here?
I've released you
to Sto-Vo-Kor.
You can't free me
until you free yourself.
I don't understand.
You never did.
I did everything
that the ritual told me to do.
I came back for you...
Forget the ritual.
It's meaningless.
Meaningless?
I died for you.
No, you didn't.
It's not your time.
You still
don't understand this journey.
Then tell me.
Request denied.
What do you want?
Who are you asking?
You, Kahless, the tooth fairy!
Anybody who will tell me
what I am supposed to do!
You are the only one
who can answer that question.
Choose to live, B'Elanna.
PARIS:
Neural activity's at 23 percent.
Initiate cortical stimulation.
Pulses at 50 millijoules.
No effect.
Increase to
70 millijoules.
Come on, B'Elanna.
Defend yourself.
You want me to fight?
You want me to be
a good little Klingon?
( grunts )
( thunder cracks )
Is that it?
You've let your anger
consume you.
Now it's consuming us.
She has condemned us all.
Misery loves company.
Get away from me!
Or what?
You'll kill us
where we stand?
Tell me what you want me to be!
A good Starfleet
officer?
A good Maquis?
Lover?
Daughter?
Just tell me
what you want from me!
We don't want anything
from you, B'Elanna.
We only want you.
We're not your enemies.
Defend yourself.
I don't know how.
I am so tired of fighting.
We know.
( yells )
You've taken the first
step of your journey.
And what about you?
We will see
each other again.
In Sto-Vo-Kor?
Yes,
in Sto-Vo-Kor.
Or maybe... when
you get home.
Mother?
Oh, God, I'm alive.
Welcome back.