DOCTOR:
Somewhere in that totality
known as the universe
is a galaxy
called the Milky Way.
Tucked into the corner
of that galaxy
is a planet named Earth.
On that planet
is a city called Mantua.
Go straight ahead
past the fountain,
turn right, then left,
then right again.
You'll find yourself
walking along the water,
listening as a man sings
of his beloved's
unfaithful heart.
And even the fish
begin to weep.
"Quando la donna è mobile."
♪ La donna è mobile ♪
♪ Qual piuma al vento ♪
♪ Muta d'accento ♪
♪ E di pensiero ♪
♪ Sempre un'amabile ♪
♪ Leggiadro viso ♪
♪ In pianto, o in riso ♪
♪ E' menzognero ♪
♪ La donna è mobile ♪
♪ Qual piuma al vento ♪
♪ Muta d'accento ♪
( sniffles )
♪ E di pensier ♪
♪ E di pensier... ♪
Tuvok.
♪ E di pensier. ♪
( laughing )
( groans )
Tuvok.
( grunts )
Janeway to Security.
Get a team to the Mess Hall
right away.
Stand back.
He's been seized
by the Pon farr.
A neurochemical imbalance
is driving him to mate.
We won't be able
to reason with him.
♪ Tuvok, I understand ♪
♪ You are a Vulcan man ♪
♪ You have just gone without ♪
♪ For seven years about ♪
♪ Paris, please find a way ♪
♪ To load a hypospray ♪
♪ I will give you the sign ♪
♪ Just aim for his behind ♪
♪ Hormones are raging ♪
♪ Synapses blazing ♪
♪ It's all so ve... ♪
♪ ...ry illogical ♪
♪ Illogical ♪
♪ Ill... ♪
♪ Illogical. ♪
Bravo!
( cheers and applause )
( cheering and applause )
TORRES:
Doctor?
Hello?
Hmm.
( clears throat )
Maybe I'd better
run a diagnostic
on your hearing subroutines.
My hearing's fine.
I was just letting
my mind wander, that's all.
If you're not working
on anything, you should
deactivate yourself.
Save us the energy.
Wait a second.
I thought I was scheduled
to go on the away team.
The planet looks pretty safe
on the long-range sensors.
Any medical problems, and
we can just use the transporter.
But take a look at those scans,
see if there's anything
we might have missed.
Lieutenant, I wanted
to go on the away team.
There's a canyon on that planet
I'd like to investigate.
I've already
handed out assignments.
Next time.
If you'd like, I'll snap
a few images for you.
Don't bother.
Suit yourself.
I'll just use my imagination.
CHAKOTAY:
Where did that
come from?
Good question.
Didn't show up on sensors
until a few minutes ago.
T-class nebula.
1,000 kilometer
diameter.
Hydrogen, helium...
argon.
Nothing too dramatic.
If you want some drama,
take a look at this.
"To Captain Kathryn Janeway,
Starship Voyager
from Emergency Medical
Hologram, Starship Voyager.
Topic: Status of Emergency
Medical Hologram,
Starship Voyager."
He's filing a
formal grievance.
Regarding?
His treatment by the crew.
There's also a paragraph
about his future
on Voyager
and a proposal
for his advancement.
"Failure
to acknowledge sentience."
"Rude behavior."
What's this?
A request to be "made Captain
in the event
of a catastrophic emergency."
He's serious?
Dead serious,
and he wants
a formal response...
for the record.
Protocol allows
for Commander Chakotay
or myself
to address his demands,
if the Captain
would prefer.
No, I'll take care of it.
I don't want anybody
to be uncomfortable
on this ship.
I guess we should
all try to be a little more
considerate of his feelings.
Captain, he does it to himself.
He's Chief Medical Officer.
Is it our fault
that's not enough for him?
Resume course
toward the planet.
Chakotay, you have the Bridge.
I've got a formal response
to draft.
MALE:
What category did I
assign that vessel?
Unacceptable risk.
Correct.
And what was
my justification
for that decision?
The ship appears
in none of our databases.
Initial attempts
to scan the interior failed.
Then why are you
wasting our resources?
I-I think I can
penetrate the hull...
uh, using a micro-tunneling
sensor...
And observe the interior
one molecule at a time?
There are
other potential targets
that must be surveyed.
If I could tap into
a data transfer conduit,
I'd be able to reach
their main computer core.
That would tell me
all we need to know
about their tactical
systems... in theory.
We could be detected.
They may not like
being spied upon.
I think I've been
very careful avoiding this.
I'll take every precaution--
I promise!
Unacceptable risk.
I've already transmitted
my proposal to the Hierarchy.
They should be
responding momentarily.
Do you have something
you'd like to say?
No.
The Hierarchy cannot be bothered
with every ill-conceived
notion that you...
( beeping )
They've approved.
I'd better get started.
You're too
confrontational.
He'll report you.
Humph.
Acceptable risk.
The layer of antonium
runs right along the edge
of the canyon.
My scans show
geological instability
within 100 meters of
the target location.
I could put the Flyer
down just outside of that.
NEELIX:
I don't know, Tom.
That might be
a little too far.
PARIS:
What's the matter, Neelix?
Afraid of a little exercise?
Well, I think we could handle
a 100-meter stroll.
PARIS:
I have to agree.
NEELIX:
Maybe getting there.
It's coming back
I'm worried about.
We'll be loaded
down with ore.
If the ground
is unstable...
I suggest limiting the team
members to 20 kilograms.
Preliminary scans indicate
the crust is dense enough
to support that weight.
You might try carrying
a transport enhancer
to the site.
NEELIX:
That's not a bad idea.
We'll beam the ore back
to the Delta Flyer--
and we won't have
to carry anything.
TORRES:
You know, this mission
is starting to look
a little more dangerous
than we thought.
Maybe we do need
the Doctor to come along.
If one of us fell
through the crust,
there could be injuries.
I require the Doctor's
assistance in Astrometrics.
What for?
That's none of your business.
I think it is.
( groaning )
What's wrong, Captain?
It's nothing, really.
An old Academy injury.
Flares up
every now and then.
I've learned
to live with it,
but maybe you should
stay here and have a look.
Right...
there.
Get away from him!
You ... are dismissed.
( satisfied sigh )
Doctor?
Yes... Captain.
Let's talk about
these demands of yours.
I've given you a great deal
of freedom on this ship.
I'm not disputing that.
But you're not
satisfied, either.
I should be allowed
to participate
and advance
according to my abilities,
like any other member
of this crew.
You should also
know your limits.
My program can be
expanded indefinitely.
I don't have limits.
Maybe.
But we all have primary
responsibilities.
Yours is Sick Bay.
I'm a computer program.
Multiple tasking
is second nature to me.
This proposal of yours...
to be made a... what?
What did you call it?
ECH--
Emergency Command
Hologram.
In principle, it's
an interesting idea.
A backup Captain
in case I'm
incapacitated,
and the command
structure breaks down.
But expanding your program
would take months of work.
The lives of the crew
may depend on it someday.
I'm afraid
the answer is no, Doctor.
However, as part of
my formal response,
I have recommended
that Starfleet assign
a team of engineers
to consider your proposal.
When we get back to
the Alpha Quadrant,
I'll pass it along.
Thank you, Captain.
Thank you, Doctor.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to introduce
the Emergency
Command Hologram.
Hear, hear.
( applause )
Congratulations.
I've tried to access
their internal sensors,
but I couldn't get past
the security encryption.
So I found something
even better--
a holographic crewman.
I've tapped into his
cognitive subroutines.
We can now monitor
everything he's experiencing.
It's like having
an agent on board.
To the ECH.
Captain,
this is such an honor,
but if you don't mind my saying,
hardly a surprise.
( all laughing )
( satisfied sigh )
Allow me to introduce...
the Doctor.
He's a computer program--
a sentient piece
of holographic technology--
and he is Voyager's
Medical Officer.
"Voyager"?
That's the name of the ship.
I've only been
observing the Doctor
for a matter of hours,
and I've already learned
more about this vessel
than I did in three days
of sensor sweeps.
Elaborate.
The reason Voyager
is not in our database
is because they are not
from this quadrant.
They're... lost...
alone.
No backup vessel?
Uh-huh.
No one to contact for help?
Precisely.
Another few hours of
observation and I will know
all we need to know
about them-- defenses,
weapons, crew complement--
everything.
From monitoring one individual?
Unlikely.
Actually...
it is very likely.
The social structure
on Voyager
is-is much different
than ours.
How so?
This is
my observation post.
I have a single function,
but the Doctor...
does much more
than just practice medicine.
He has access
to the entire ship.
And he seems to be
an expert on... everything.
In fact, the Captain
just gave him authorization
to command the bridge!
It was a very...
exciting moment.
Why aren't you
monitoring him now?
Well, the link drops out
intermittently,
but it should be reestablished
in a few minutes.
Maintain your surveillance.
This'll take care
of any potential allergens
in the planet's atmosphere.
I'll monitor your medical
status from the bridge,
but I don't anticipate
any problems.
Since I'm not going,
I wonder if you'd mind
snapping a few holo-images
for me while you're
down there.
Gladly.
Tell me something,
Mr. Neelix.
Do you... daydream?
On Talaxia,
we have a saying--
"The dream dreams
the dreamer."
Care to translate?
We like to think
that fantasies and daydreams
come from someplace else--
another land.
They slip into our minds
and whisper about things
we never imagined.
A strange notion.
Do you daydream, Doctor?
No, of course not.
I'm a computer program.
I prefer wide shots,
Mr. Neelix.
If you're
feeling creative,
throw in a little ultraviolet.
Will do.
( chuckling )
Voyager to Delta Flyer.
Report.
PARIS:
We're approaching the canyon.
Phew, what a view.
I'm sure it is.
JANEWAY: Put us in
a synchronous orbit
above their
landing coordinates.
Voyager, Mayday!
What's wrong?
( staticky ):
We've been hit.
I'm taking us down
into the canyon...
Harry...
I don't know
what happened to them.
I am picking up a vessel,
Captain.
It's Borg.
Red alert.
On screen.
Battle stations.
Captain...
you must relieve me
of duty at once.
An assimilation virus
has penetrated our defenses.
We're becoming drones.
Hard to Starboard.
Reinforce the shields.
Incoming fire!
Doctor...
Computer, activate the ECH.
Acknowledged.
Transferring all systems
to your command.
You have the bridge.
Indeed.
Shields to maximum.
Photon torpedoes, full volley.
Fire.
Computer, report.
Enemy shields are intact.
We are the Borg.
I know very well who you are.
Stand down your weapons.
State your designation.
Emergency Command Hologram,
at your service.
Designation unknown.
Not for long.
Doctor...
COMPUTER:
Warning.
Primary shields are failing.
This is the last time
I'm going to ask you.
Stand down your weapons.
Turn back while you still can.
You will be assimilated.
Over my dead program.
Computer,
activate the photonic cannon.
The photonic cannon is on line.
Fire.
KIM:
Doctor, can you confirm?
The readings, Doctor.
Um, the, uh...
Uh...
readings, uh...
confirm, of course.
Uh, the away team's
physiologies
are within acceptable
parameters.
All life signs stable.
You're okay to
proceed, Tom.
PARIS:
Understood.
We'll contact you again
when we reach the site.
Voyager will not
be an easy target.
It is armed with
something called
"a photonic cannon".
I watched them destroy
a Borg sphere with
a single volley.
There are no reports
of Borg in this region.
I saw it
with my own eyes.
Did you check
for debris?
The ship was annihilated.
There was nothing left
for the sensors to pick up.
Continue.
Their Captain was disabled
in the attack.
The hologram is now in command.
He's...
an impressive individual--
a physician, an engineer...
a warrior--
and very attractive
to the females.
We must at all cost try to avoid
a direct confrontation with him.
I recommend
a type-3 stealth assault.
The Hierarchy approves.
Prepare
for a stealth assault
type-3.
Scan for Borg.
We don't want
any last-minute surprises...
or mistakes.
Doctor...
can I have a
word with you?
I know I let my attention
drift a little on the bridge,
but I assure you...
Are you kidding?
That was incredible.
I just wanted to
congratulate you.
For what exactly?
The Borg will have
to think twice
about attacking
Voyager again.
Nice work.
Computer, locate
Commander Chakotay.
Commander Chakotay is
in his quarters.
Something wrong?
TORRES:
What were you trying to do?
I've been
experimenting
with introducing
a new function
into my program--
cognitive projections...
daydreaming.
I wanted to be
able to daydream.
An inefficient activity.
We all do it
now and then, Seven.
Why not the Doctor?
My thought exactly.
So, what's the problem?
The algorithms
are malfunctioning.
I'm starting to daydream...
whether I want to or not.
They say a Doctor
who operates on himself
has a p'takh for a patient.
I can help him.
I'm sure you can.
The Doctor and I
are going to Sick Bay.
Any excuse to be
alone with him,
eh, Seven?
Assimilation is
an unpleasant fate.
Is that a threat?
( alarm blaring )
This is impossible.
The warp containment field
is failing!
COMPUTER:
Warp core breach in 30 seconds.
Try stabilizing
the antimatter flow.
The control linkage
is down.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Warp core breach
a lot sooner than you think.
TORRES: We've got to get
someone inside the warp core...
try to eject it manually.
No one could survive
the current level
of plasma radiation.
The Doctor.
This isn't real...
is it?
Doc, you're the only one
who can help us.
Warning. Last chance
to be a hero, Doctor.
Get going.
Here's the problem.
The new algorithms
weren't isolated properly.
They've branched
into his perceptual subroutines.
Doc, why don't we
take a closer look
at the matrix and...
What are you doing?
I have to eject
the core.
What?!
Deactivate his program.
No, it will damage his matrix.
Don't try to stop me.
Let's take him
to Sick Bay.
I have
to save the ship!
I have to save the ship!
You look lovely tonight, Seven.
Where shall we go?
That sounds wonderful.
The new algorithms
have completely
taken over his program.
Ambassador!
So, now he's
daydreaming
constantly?
It's a photonic cannon.
I designed it myself.
He seems to be randomly jumping
from one to the next.
Oh. Pardon me, Miss.
I routed his subroutines
to Holodeck 1,
so Harry and Seven
could monitor his fantasies.
Do you think
that's appropriate?
They're his fantasies,
and I promised him
we'd show a little
more consideration.
It'll give us a better idea
of what's going on,
help us fix him.
Mr. Neelix, how thoughtful.
You baked me a cake...
Kim to Sick Bay.
Go ahead, Harry.
You might want
to have a look at this.
We're on our way.
Mm-hmm.
Keep still, please.
Anything you say, Doctor.
He does the hands
very well.
Apparently,
he's had a great
deal of practice.
Look at these.
( alarm blaring )
Computer... activate
the Emergency Command Hologram.
This is the
part I like.
Nice touch.
Bring the photonic cannon
on line.
Photonic cannon?
A weapon of mass
destruction,
invented by the
Doctor, of course.
Of course.
In many of his fantasies,
he takes command
and saves the ship.
I see.
Which means that
particular algorithm
is more easily accessible
than the others.
So, if we can isolate it,
we might be able to
stabilize his program.
TORRES:
Why do you torment
me like this?
DOCTOR:
That was never my intention.
It wasn't?
I want you to be
happy, B'Elanna.
( sighs ):
Without you?
What?!
Shh...
I'll always be...
fond of you.
That will never change.
You can't just leave me.
I couldn't bear to be alone.
Aren't you
forgetting someone?
He needs you, B'Elanna,
now more than ever.
Forget him.
He's not half the man you are.
Mm-hmm. Well...
I've seen enough of this.
All right, let's go
back to Sick Bay
and try to isolate
that algorithm.
Congratulations.
Thank you for this
opportunity, Captain.
All I've ever
wanted was
to live up to my
full potential...
to hone all my skills...
expand my abilities...
to help the people I love.
MALE:
What's the status?
I lost the signal again.
I don't know what happened.
Two assault vessels are
on course to join us.
Accurate information
is essential!
The more I learn
about Voyager,
the more I wonder...
if it's worth the trouble.
Clarify.
Launching an attack
against such
a heavily armed vessel
carries a great risk,
and for what?
A little antimatter
and some dilithium...
Your survey indicated
large quantities of both.
We've already committed
substantial resources
to mounting
this assault.
Were you mistaken?
No!
( stammering ):
Not at all.
I'm just...
sounding a note of caution.
If our boarding party
doesn't find Voyager
exactly as you've
described it...
the Hierarchy
will be informed.
I understand.
There has been no mistake.
Then we'll proceed.
I've made
a terrible mistake.
How... terrible?
The Doctor was appearing
in a different location
every few seconds.
It didn't seem possible.
So, I investigated
a little further and...
I haven't been monitoring
his perceptions.
I've been watching
his dreams...
or his... his imaginings.
I'm not sure which...
but none of this is real.
What am I going to do?
( door opens,
footsteps approach )
I came to check
on your patient.
He's doing just fine, Captain.
It took Lieutenant Torres
half the night
to stabilize my matrix,
but I haven't had
a single flight of fancy since.
I apologize for altering
my program without permission.
Well, at least
there wasn't
any permanent damage.
( sighs ):
I'm afraid there was.
I've been exposed...
humiliated...
turned inside out
for all the world to see.
If I've lost your respect...
That will never happen...
certainly not because we've seen
a few random fantasies.
We all daydream, Doctor.
It helps us imagine
other possibilities
in life.
Just hold off until
we've figured out
a way for you to do it
without damaging
yourself, all right?
( door chimes )
JANEWAY:
Come in.
Ship status report.
Federation Law.
Thinking about
a career change?
In a way.
Not for me, though.
I've been going over
the legal precedents
for granting command positions
to holograms.
There aren't any.
Captain, this ship
needs its Doctor.
He should focus on what
he was programmed for--
medical care.
I think we've
underestimated him
because of our own
human limitations.
His full potential's
unknown, Chakotay.
Would you be comfortable
handing over your ship
to a computer program?
Well, I don't know
if I'd take it that far.
You might have to.
He probably won't
settle for less.
( buzz of conversation )
Oh, no.
Allow me
to shake your hand.
Congratulations.
Doctor, may I please
have a word with you?
I don't recall
dreaming you up.
You didn't.
I'm transmitting
a simulation of myself
into your program,
but I am real.
Doctor to the Bridge.
I'm daydreaming again.
Somebody deactivate me.
Voyager is
about to be attacked.
Of course it is,
unless the valiant Doctor
swings into action, right?
Yes, yes, precisely.
A common theme in
all my fantasies.
I reactivated your
cognitive algorithms.
I put you back into
this... fiction.
( whispering )
Here. Why?
It was the only way for me
to communicate with you.
I'm listening.
I'm a long-range observer
on an assault-class vessel.
I scan passing ships
for technology
and raw materials.
When I find an acceptable
target, we raid it.
You've been
spying on us.
More to the point-- on you.
For several days,
I've been using
a long-range tunneling sensor
to tap into your program.
You were supposed to be
our eyes and ears
on Voyager.
Instead, I got this.
My daydreams?!
You tapped into
my daydreams?!
That's why my algorithms
have been destabilizing.
My fault. I'm sorry.
Tell me about this attack.
My ship is less
than an hour away.
I can help you avoid
a confrontation,
but you must do
exactly what I say.
Why should you
want to help us?
You don't understand.
The Hierarchy
does not tolerate mistakes
or misinformation.
If they learn of my error...
I'll lose my livelihood.
Well, that's what
you get for being
a Peeping Tom.
But I also care
about what happens to you.
I feel like
I've gotten to know you
over the past few days.
You've been spying
on my fantasies, not me.
You don't know me at all.
But I do.
I know how your mind works...
what your hopes are.
You created all these...
possibilities.
My species, we're...
very different.
Our thinking is confined, but...
I can't help...
but admire you.
I don't want you
to be harmed.
Then I suppose we should
swing into action.
Captain, we're
about to be attacked.
Alien vessels
are approaching.
There's nothing
on the sensors, Doc.
The vessels are cloaked.
How do you know this?
One of the aliens
contacted me.
TUVOK: I've detected
no transmissions.
He spoke to me in a daydream.
I don't want to hear it.
However, I would like to
know why you've disobeyed
my direct order.
I can prove it to you.
The alien told me
how to reconfigure our sensors
to compensate
for their cloaking field.
He's right.
I'm picking up
three ships
out there-- distance,
600 million kilometers,
headed right for us.
On screen.
Maximum magnification.
The alien won't help us
unless we help him.
What if this is all part
of their attack? A ruse?
He's already helped us
compensate for their cloak.
I'm inclined to believe him.
So am I, but I'd just as soon
set a course away from here
at maximum warp.
That will only delay
a confrontation.
They have vessels
hidden throughout
the entire sector.
Did your friend have a plan?
He said they're
running what's called
a type-3 stealth assault.
They won't de-cloak
until they're right
on top of us,
at which point they'll
fire a warning shot
across our bow.
Then come the demands--
for supplies and technology.
If we don't comply,
they'll destroy us.
Fortunately,
the alien promised
to transmit the resonance
frequencies of their phasers.
And in return?
In return...
He mistakenly informed
his superiors
that I was in command
of Voyager.
To keep himself
from being demoted,
he wants us...
to maintain that fiction.
When they open the channel,
I have to be sitting
in the Captain's chair.
I'm sorry, Captain...
but he insisted.
Well, I guess it's time
to turn fantasy into reality.
I'm in over my head.
What if I fail?
You sound like I did
when the Captain put me
in command of the night shift.
That chair looked so big,
I thought I'd sink
so far into it
that nobody
would be able to see me.
But you had your Academy
training to fall back on.
Yeah, well, sounds like you've
had plenty of practice.
That wasn't real.
Listen, Doc...
the whole reason
you wanted to be
able to daydream
was to test out
possibilities, right?
Well, consider
this a field test.
Why isn't there any hull damage
from the Borg attack?
They... repaired it.
So quickly? Hmm.
Prepare for type-4 assault.
Type-4?
That would cause a huge drain
on our energy core--
a... a waste of resources.
Do you really think
that's necessary?
What I think doesn't matter.
Your long-range surveillance
indicated an attack by Borg.
On closer inspection,
that appears to be doubtful.
Your report on this vessel
could be mistaken.
I think caution is in order.
The Hierarchy agrees.
Proceed to type-4.
Captain on the bridge.
( gasps )
It won't bite.
What I wouldn't give right now
for a whoopee cushion.
A what?
( chuckling )
Ancient technology.
( beeping loudly )
Captain, we're ready to proceed.
Acknowledged, Commander.
The internal
com-link is active.
No one will be able to
hear you but the Doctor.
Doctor, are you ready?
No, but do I
have a choice?
I'll be with you
every step of the way.
Just remember,
I'm still the captain.
Understood.
I'm receiving a transmission
on a secure channel--
audio only.
Must be the
Doctor's friend.
Let's hear what
he has to say.
Doctor?
Hello? Voyager here.
It's me.
ALIEN ( quietly ): Doctor,
something terrible has happened.
They've ordered
a type-4 assault.
Our phaser frequencies
will be rotated continuously.
I won't be able to help you.
Evasive maneuvers.
TUVOK: Three vessels
are de-cloaking
off the port bow.
That didn't feel like
a warning shot.
Direct hit.
Shields are holding.
They're hailing us.
This is it, Doctor.
On screen.
You see? There he is.
Uh...
be careful.
He-he-he's dangerous.
The Hierarchy controls
this region of space.
Your ship has supplies
and technology that we require.
Tell him
we'll defend ourselves.
They won't get
what they're after.
We'll defend ourselves.
They won't get
what they're after.
Huh?
I mean you... won't get
what you're after.
Not in a million years.
Not if I have anything
to say about it!
Don't improvise, Doctor.
Sorry.
MALE:
An exchange of fire
would damage both of our ships,
but we have support nearby.
You are alone.
Take your weapons off-line
and prepare to be b...
TUVOK:
Excuse the interruption,
Commander.
I've found a potential weakness
in their shields,
but I'll need time
to reconfigure our phasers.
Keep him occupied,
Doctor. On screen.
( stammering )
This is my final warning.
Don't... rush me.
Take your weapons off-line.
Immediately.
I won't ask again.
You...
appear to be suffering
from a physio-emotive disorder.
You're impatient,
quick to anger.
Do you have any idea what that
does to your vascular pressure?
You may want to see a physician.
Firing phasers.
Direct hit.
Ha!
How do you like that, huh?
A taste of your own medicine!
JANEWAY:
Tone it down, Doctor.
Sorry.
Our phasers are off-line.
Prepare to be boarded.
JANEWAY:
It's time to negotiate, Doctor.
Tell them...
Tuvok!
Activate the photonic cannon.
Tuvok, that was an order!
Activating
the photonic cannon...
sir.
I'd rather not give the order
to fire.
My sensors are showing
no activation sequence.
Of course not. The photonic
cannon is impervious to sensors.
The Borg couldn't
detect it either.
That's why they
were destroyed.
The Borg, the Hierarchy--
it's all the same to me.
Just another bully who didn't
know when to back off.
We'll be vaporized.
( both sighing )
The Hierarchy
suggests retreat.
( sighing )
They're moving away
at maximum impulse.
Go ahead, Doctor.
You've earned it.
Seven of Nine to the Doctor.
Go ahead.
I require your assistance
in the mess hall.
( sighing )
I'll be right there.
ALL: Surprise!
( applause )
Don't worry, Doc.
You're not dreaming.
Captain?
For your imaginative defense
of this ship and her crew,
I'm awarding you the Starfleet
Medal of Commendation.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I've also reconsidered
your request.
I'm going to authorize
a research project
to explore
your command abilities.
You're a natural.
Congratulations, Doctor.
That was a platonic gesture.
Don't expect me
to pose for you.
Noted.