PARIS:
All right, all right, hold on.
If you were married in 2304,
and your daughter was conceived
during your 11th Pon farr,
that would make you...
162 years old.
Incorrect.
KIM: Come on, Tom.
The man's not
a day over 140.
We know you were
at least a hundred
when you joined Starfleet
the second time,
so I'm guessing
you're around 133?
Also incorrect.
I'm afraid you both lack
sufficient data
to reach
a logical conclusion.
Come on, Tuvok,
tell us.
I see no reason
to enlighten you.
Don't tell me Vulcans
are embarrassed
about their age.
On the contrary,
we value the wisdom
that comes with
advancing years.
In that case,
how wise are you?
Wise enough to end
this inquiry.
( console beeping )
Saved by the bell.
I've got a fleet
of ships
200,000 kilometers
dead ahead.
TUVOK: Can you identify them?
Negative.
I'm reading multiple
hull configurations.
Raise shields.
Red Alert.
JANEWAY:
Report.
We've detected a large
group of vessels
directly ahead.
Hostile?
TUVOK: Possibly.
I'm charging weapons.
On screen.
KIM:
I'm counting 62 ships
and a few hundred
pieces of ships,
all dead in space.
( sighs ):
It's a junkyard.
Congratulations, Tuvok.
You just saved us from
a flotilla of hostile trash.
( communications beep )
KIM: We're being hailed.
JANEWAY:
Let's see what they want.
Welcome to Abaddon's Repository
of Lost Treasures.
Whether you're in the mood
to buy or simply browse,
we're always open.
Take a look.
You may find something
you never knew you wanted.
CHAKOTAY:
Mr. Abaddon.
The name was passed down
from my father
and his father before him.
Not a very imaginative lot,
but I'll answer to it
just the same.
I'm Commander Chakotay.
This is Mr. Neelix.
Welcome to Voyager.
Neelix, is it?
You wouldn't be
a fellow trader, would you?
What makes you
say that?
Cheerful demeanor,
furtive eyes.
It's obvious
you're a man of commerce.
You're very perceptive,
Mr. Abaddon.
A useful skill
in my line of work.
Oh, I'll admit
there was a time
when I dabbled
in commerce,
but these days,
I focus my efforts
on food and diplomacy.
Well, whether you're
interested
in a new
iso-convective oven
or a slightly dated
translation matrix,
you've come
to the right place.
My inventory,
give or take a few items.
After 20 years,
it's hard to keep up.
Looks like you have
an item or two we might
be interested in.
Uh, the question is
what are you looking
for in return?
Artificial
gravity plating.
( gasps ): Plasma-based
power induction. Impressive.
Those are
integrated systems.
Unfortunately, we couldn't
trade them to you
without dismantling
our whole ship.
Commander, don't
we have some spare
duranium sheeting
in Cargo Bay 1?
With a few
modifications, uh,
it could be converted
into gravity plating.
Good idea. Why don't you show
Mr. Abaddon our inventory?
Report back
when you're done.
Yes, sir. Mr. Abaddon,
follow me, please.
KIM:
This guy's collected more
technology than the Borg.
And almost all of it
is useless.
Wait. What's that?
Ensign?
Grid 49-Alpha.
Oh, she's beautiful.
It's just
an old rust bucket.
What, are you kidding?
Look at those lines.
It's a work of art.
That ship wasn't assembled;
it was sculpted.
I think I'm in love.
NEELIX:
That makes 15 power regulators
in fair condition
and three more we could salvage
with a little work.
Seven has some doubts
about the ion exchange rods...
We'll take a chance.
Add them to the list.
What about these
cultural artifacts?
Oh, just a few items
I thought might have
some historical value.
They don't cost much.
Looks like a good haul.
If that's it...
Oh, uh, yes, there is
one other item:
uh, a small vessel
that could be an asset.
We've already got
a full complement
of shuttles,
not to mention
the Delta Flyer.
What do we need with
this derelict ship?
Chakotay, this ship
is a diamond in the rough.
Sure, it's got
some scrapes and scratches,
but, here, take a look
at these systems.
It has a neurogenic
interface
that allows
it to react
directly to the
pilot's thoughts.
That gives it the potential
of being quicker
and more maneuverable
than anything we've got,
including the
Delta Flyer.
Add to that
an optronic weapons array...
I get the picture.
Are you sure you're
not just looking
for a new toy?
No. Absolutely not.
Even B'Elanna thinks
restoring this ship
is worthwhile.
Maybe, if we had the
manpower to restore it.
No, I'll do all the work
myself on my own time...
and if I need a hand,
Harry's offered to help.
I have?
( sighs ):
What will it cost us?
Abaddon's agreed to give it
to us for three used power cells
and Tom's interactive
record collection.
My jukebox.
All right.
One slightly
used alien ship.
Don't make me
regret this.
You won't.
Remember, just one seat.
Not much storage.
She was designed for
speed, not hauling.
Understood.
Make sure you go easy
on the thrusters.
She doesn't like
being manhandled.
Temperamental?
Sensitive.
She demands respect,
like any fine piece
of machinery.
Sounds like you're sorry
to let her go.
In some ways, she's like
the daughter that I
couldn't marry off,
but that doesn't mean
I'd trade her
to just anyone.
I've got a feeling
you're the kind of
pilot that she needs,
someone that'll give
her the proper care
and attention.
I'm your man.
Don't worry, Mr. Abaddon.
She's in good hands.
Well, this has been
a very productive exchange.
Oh, just one more thing...
Uh, let me guess.
All trades are final.
( chuckles )
PARIS:
I still can't get
an active readout.
KIM:
Here's the reason.
Another damaged
power cell.
( sighs ):
Come on, Alice,
how 'bout it?
Give us a break.
Alice?
Well, I've got
to call her something.
How about
the Lost Cause?
( chuckles ):
Alice Battisti was
"the lost cause."
I knew her back at the Academy.
She was smart, sexy...
but she wouldn't give me
the time of day.
All right,
Alice it is.
Try it again.
I've got a pulse!
( laughs )
A little snug.
As Seven would say,
an efficient design.
The main computer's
coming on line.
There's not much in it.
Just a few schematics.
Looks like somebody tried
to wipe the database.
Probably rolled the
odometer back, too.
Let's see what
this neurogenic
interface can do.
Whoa.
What's it like?
It's kind of hard
to describe.
I'm tapped into all
the primary systems:
ops, tactical,
sensors...
What happened?
We just blew out
two more power cells.
( groans )
See if you can
reconfigure the power
distribution grid.
Look, we're both tired.
Why don't we call it a night,
come back fresh tomorrow?
Oh, come on, we can
still get a couple
more hours in.
You can get
a couple more hours in.
I'm going to bed.
All right. You win.
Good night, Alice.
See you in the morning.
PARIS:
Good night, Alice.
See you in the morning.
PARIS AND FEMALE VOICE:
FEMALE VOICE:
See you in the morning.
( woman whispering ):
Tom...
B'Elanna?
Tom?
Who are you?
It's me, Alice.
Good morning, Alice.
PARIS: I'm sorry,
but you're going to have
to trust me on this.
You'll be a lot happier
if we can bypass
the EPS relays.
Tom.
Yeah?
Who are you
talking to?
Alice. She's being
very stubborn today.
No matter what I do,
I can't get her
to bring her propulsion
systems on line.
Next question:
What are you wearing?
Oh, this is a
flight suit design
I found in
Alice's database,
something her last
pilot used to wear.
( chuckles ):
For a minute, I thought you were
changing Captain Proton's look.
Chapter 37?
Oh, "The Web
of Pain."
I completely forgot.
Oh, no problem-- I've got
another hour on the holodeck.
You know, now is
not a great time.
How 'bout tomorrow?
That's what you
said yesterday.
Sorry, Harry.
Alice needs me.
So does Arachnia.
Give the queen
my regards.
( sighs )
Okay...
Seven, can I get you
something?
A refund. The star charts
we obtained from Abaddon
are inaccurate.
Really?
The computations are
based on obsolete data.
It's not the only item
that didn't live up
to its advertising.
SEVEN:
Cultural artifacts?
According to Abaddon,
they're lost treasures
of the Delta Quadrant.
If you ask me,
they're worthless trinkets.
Perhaps not.
This crystal
is beryllium.
Valuable?
Beryllium is the
standard currency
in Spatial Grid 539.
There are species
that would trade
an entire fleet
of starships for
this "trinket."
If Abaddon knew about this,
he'd never have traded it
for a few plasma couplings.
Well, maybe
I should return it.
Need I remind you?
All trades are final.
Neelix, I need one
bottle of champagne,
if you don't mind.
Another anniversary?
No. I'm christening
Alice.
Congratulations.
I'll whip up some hors d'oeuvres
for the crew.
Oh, no, don't bother.
This is a private ceremony.
Just me and B'Elanna.
And Alice, of course.
Oh, yes, of course.
There's nothing like having
your own ship.
I remember
when I first laid eyes
on my little freighter,
Baxial.
No, don't tell me--
love at first sight?
Actually, I thought she was
the ugliest thing I ever saw.
( both laughing )
But she grew on me.
Eventually, I-I couldn't
imagine being without her.
You know, she's still down
in the Shuttle Bay.
Why don't we get her
and Alice together
and go on a double date?
You pack the
picnic basket.
I'll bring
the deuterium.
So, I finally get
to meet the other woman.
Don't be too critical.
She's a long way
from finished.
When have you ever known me
to be critical?
( laughs ):
Is that a trick question?
Okay, ready?
Well?
It's beautiful.
I can hardly believe
it's the same ship.
( chuckles ):
Yeah. Most of it isn't.
I've replaced
the impulse reactor,
navigational array,
uh, plasma manifolds...
The list goes on and on.
Just a few more repairs,
and she'll be spaceworthy.
Care to do the honors?
It's almost a shame
to break this over the hull.
You have a point.
Oh, oh, be careful--
the upholstery.
I'll send an Engineering team
down to clean it up.
( chuckles )
To Alice.
So, when's
her first flight?
Well, a couple of days,
if I can round up
all the parts I need.
You want to
come with me?
Sure there's room?
It'll be a
tight squeeze.
We'll manage.
( console beeping )
Hold on.
Something wrong?
It's these
environmental controls.
They need recalibrating.
It is kind of warm
in here, isn't it?
Alice, lower
the ambient temperature.
Please specify, Tom.
Five degrees
should do it.
Temperature modification
complete.
That's some voice.
It came with the ship.
You jealous?
Maybe I should be.
I hear you've been
sleeping here.
When Alice
lets me sleep.
Sounds like a real
slave driver.
Well, if you're trying
to make improvements,
you might want to start
with these reactant
injectors.
The deuterium
mix is too high.
Well, that's
how Alice likes it.
No, don't touch that.
I was just
trying to help.
Well, thanks,
but we're fine.
"We"? It's a ship, Tom.
Yeah, but she's my ship.
Well, then, maybe
I'll leave the two
of you alone.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
Thanks for
the champagne.
( groans )
Oh, sorry.
I need to fix that.
CHAKOTAY:
30 meters of
EPS conduit,
a broadband
sensor matrix,
a tactical
data module.
Tom, I appreciate
your enthusiasm,
but I can't spare
these parts right now.
But they're just lying
around Cargo Bay 2.
Those are emergency
supplies,
and this isn't
an emergency.
Okay, what if I just
replicated some?
That takes energy,
which isn't exactly in
abundance at the moment.
Maybe in a few weeks,
if we can replenish
our power reserve.
A few weeks?
What am I supposed to do
until then?
Your duties, which
you've been neglecting.
You've been late for
two shifts in Sick Bay.
You've been distracted
on the Bridge.
Maybe it's time you gave
this project a rest.
( sighs ):
You're right.
I guess I have been
overdoing it.
You look run-down.
Maybe you should
stop by Sick Bay
and have the Doctor
take a look at you.
No. I'm fine.
I-I just haven't been
getting enough sleep.
Well, your next shift
isn't till 0700.
Why don't you do yourself
a favor and turn in early?
Yeah. Good idea.
One more thing.
I'd appreciate it
if you'd shave
and change back
into your uniform.
We do have protocols.
Yes, sir.
We'll get
your Alice flying.
Just give it some time.
Sorry, Alice, we'll have to
put the test flight on hold.
All we need
is a few lousy spare parts,
but to listen to Chakotay,
you'd think Voyager
would grind to a halt
without them.
But we're so close.
Well, he gave me
a direct order.
Since when do you care
so much about orders?
( laughs ):
I'm already an ensign.
You want to see me
busted down to cadet?
Don't take that off.
Well, I'm afraid I have
to get back into uniform.
Protocol.
Forget about protocol.
Once my repairs
are complete,
we can go somewhere
together.
Leave Voyager?
It's been a long time
since I met a pilot
I've been compatible with.
We can go anywhere
you want.
It's very
tempting, Alice,
but I can't just take off.
What's holding you back?
My job, for one thing.
My friends...
B'Elanna.
She doesn't understand you
the way I do.
None of them do.
Look, maybe we can
make the test flight
in a few weeks,
and if it goes well,
I'm sure the Captain
will assign us
on missions together,
but I can't leave Voyager.
All right.
I'm sure you know
what's best for us.
Yeah, I think I do.
You look a little tired.
How about some rest?
Sit back. Relax.
Let me help you
with this.
What are these?
Just some modifications
I made to your flight suit.
They'll help us
work together more closely.
I'll show you.
Activate the interface.
Just for a minute.
You won't regret it.
What do you say we continue
with those repairs?
ALICE:
How's it coming?
This is the last power cell.
Then we'll just need
the data module
from Section Beta-12.
What's wrong?
Well, these relays
are just tricky.
That's all.
You're not being
honest with me.
I thought we agreed to tell
each other everything.
Well, it's just...
we're compromising
vital systems.
Backup systems.
If there's an emergency,
Voyager's going
to need them.
If your friends had
been more understanding,
we wouldn't have to be
sneaking around like this.
I've spent the last six years
with these people.
They're like my family.
Sometimes you have to
leave your family behind.
They're not like us.
They're trapped by
rules and regulations.
Velocity, freedom...
they'll never understand
these things the way we do.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Of course I am.
You don't belong here.
You belong with me.
You're thinking
about your first
flight, aren't you?
Tell me.
Dad took me up
in an old S-class shuttle.
( laughs ):
Two seats, no warp drive,
manual helm controls.
I was eight years old
and I was scared
out of my wits.
You couldn't keep
the ship level.
No, not at first...
but then... came this
moment of clarity,
when suddenly,
everything made sense.
The clouds parted.
I was flying.
No matter how many starships
I've piloted since then,
I'm still chasing
that feeling.
Tomorrow, you'll
catch it...
only this time,
there won't be
any clumsy controls
to get in the way.
Just you...
me...
and the stars.
Hey.
I wasn't aware
you were assigned
to Astrometrics.
I was just, uh, passing by.
I guess curiosity
got the best of me.
Are you planning
an away mission?
You were charting
a course.
Oh, that.
Uh, no, I was
just taking a peek
at what's ahead of us.
All yours.
You've modified
your garment.
Uh, adapted, actually.
I made a few tweaks
to enhance Alice's
neurogenic interface.
You know, the "merging
of man and machine"?
Perhaps you should learn
more about this interface
before you attempt
to use it.
Convince her
it's safe.
I ran diagnostics
of every system
onboard that ship.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Perhaps I should
examine it.
Make an excuse
and leave.
It's nice of you
to offer,
but it's really
not necessary.
I have to get
back to work.
Power fluctuation's
down to 4.7 percent.
Looks like Abaddon's
regulators might
work out after all.
Keep at it--
the last thing we need
is a temperamental
power supply.
Bad day at the office?
Bad night with Tom Paris.
You're his
best friend, right?
So he tells me.
So, maybe you can explain
why every time he finds
a new hobby,
I go right
out the airlock.
I wouldn't take
it personally.
The Ferengi call
it the Five Stages
of Acquisition:
Infatuation,
Justification,
Appropriation,
Obsession and Resale.
Seems like you've only
got one stage left
before he loses
interest in that ship.
Then he's all
yours again.
Until the next infatuation.
( console beeping )
We've got a .003 drop
in the warp field output.
That's within parameters.
Not on my watch.
Somebody's removed
four power cells
from the secondary
warp assembly
without
authorization.
Whoever it was tried
to cover his tracks
by rerouting power
from adjacent cells.
Should we tell Tuvok?
Don't bother.
This is an open-
and-shut case.
Tom Paris!
Well, Alice...
looks like you've been borrowing
my things without permission.
Hey!
Computer, open the hatch.
ALICE:
Unable to comply.
Warning. Life support failure.
Torres to the Bridge.
( breathing heavily ):
Torres to Chakotay!
Anybody!
B'Elanna, what are
you doing here?
Let me out of here!
( gasping )
What the hell
happened in there?
Your ship tried to kill me.
That's ridiculous.
It sealed the... the hatch,
vented the atmosphere.
You must have
accidentally tripped the
environmental controls.
Don't you try to tell me
this was an accident.
What else could it have been?
How about pilot error?
Are you saying
that this was my fault?
What's gotten
into you?
You've been stealing
components, Tom.
Oh...
I found the power cells.
A few spare parts?
You're overreacting.
Am I?
Where are you going?
To talk to the Captain.
Wait.
There's something
wrong with you.
Listen to me!
Are you out of your mind?
Stay out of this, B'Elanna!
Or what? You'll sic Alice
on me again?
Let her go.
What were you
thinking?!
You could've
killed her!
She broke
into my database.
She was going to discover
our flight plan.
Not that it matters now.
What is that
supposed to mean?
Keep your voice down.
( sighs )
Once your girlfriend
talks to the Captain,
they'll drag you
straight to Sick Bay.
One neural scan,
and they'll know all about us.
Well, maybe
it's time they did.
Think you can
just walk away?
Watch me.
So, I guess this is
the real Tom Paris.
Life throws up a few
roadblocks, and he heads
for the nearest exit.
Get away from me!
I need you.
You should've thought of that
before you tried
to kill B'Elanna.
Sick Bay.
Remember how you felt
when you first saw me?
You knew we were
meant to be together.
I was wrong.
Think of how it feels
when you're sitting
at the helm
and the interface
is active.
It's over, Alice!
One way or the other, I'm
getting the hell away from you.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
( screaming )
What are you doing
to me?!
Convincing you to
do the right thing.
Take us to the Shuttle Bay.
We're leaving Voyager.
No!
( screams )
Please, Tom.
I don't want
to hurt you.
The Shuttle Bay, now.
( groaning )
Deck 10. Shuttle Bay.
( sighing )
This isn't the first time
you and Tom have had an argument
about how he spends
his free time.
This wasn't
a lovers' quarrel.
Captain, he practically
assaulted me.
Well, that doesn't sound
like Tom.
It wasn't Tom.
It was Alice.
Now you've lost me.
That's the name that he's
calling this new ship.
Ever since he started working
on it, he hasn't slept.
He's become irritable,
irrational...
It's not just me;
Chakotay and Harry
have noticed
the same thing.
This new ship-- it has some kind
of neurogenic interface.
Exactly. It must be having
some kind of an effect on him.
All right, I'll have the Doctor
take a look at him,
but in the meantime,
I want you...
CHAKOTAY:
Captain, we have an unauthorized
launch in progress.
Seal the Shuttle Bay doors.
KIM:
Too late. He's out.
His shields are up.
I can't get a transporter lock.
Tractor beam.
They're trying
to tractor us.
Stop them.
I can't.
You'll be able
to maneuver much better
if you complete
the interface.
How?
Activate
the connector sequence.
( groans )
We're one now, Tom.
Think of what you want me
to do, and I'll do it.
We can disrupt
their tractor beam...
with an optronic pulse.
Good. You have access
to our weapons.
Use them.
He's charging weapons.
Full power to
the shields.
He's disrupting
our tractor beam.
Increase power to the emitters.
We'll drag him in by his heels
if we have to.
He's broken free,
Captain.
Janeway to Paris.
Stand down and return to
Voyager immediately.
I'm with Alice now,
Captain. Let us go.
You know I can't do that, Tom.
She'll do anything
to get you back.
I don't blame her
for that, but we
have to stop her.
How?
You know.
He's coming about.
He's charging weapons again.
Direct hit.
Return fire.
He's gone to warp.
Track him.
He masked his warp signature.
He's gone.
ALICE:
"And Daedalus fashioned wings
from wax and feathers
and used them
to escape his prison."
That's one of my
favorite myths.
I know.
But you left out
the part where Icarus
flew too close to the sun
and his wings melted.
( chuckles )
Poetic license.
Besides, if we get
too close to a star,
we have multiphasic
shielding to protect us.
What is it?
My arms.
They feel numb.
Who needs arms
when you have wings?
You're becoming
a part of me now.
Our potential is unlimited.
Forget the old Tom Paris.
He doesn't exist anymore.
You know my policy.
We're not looking for a refund--
just some information.
That's one commodity
I don't keep in stock.
I suggest you look elsewhere.
Not until we
get some answers.
You'll find I'm prepared to
deal with disgruntled customers.
Captain, I'm reading
active weapons signatures
on three
of the derelict ships.
They are targeting
Voyager.
Before we take actions
we both might regret,
Mr. Neelix has
something to show you.
I wanted to say, uh... thank you
for this... lost treasure.
A beryllium crystal.
I'm surprised
a trader of your distinction
would let this slip
through this fingers.
I could say
all trades are final,
but we'd be willing
to give it back
in exchange
for some cooperation.
Haunted?
That's what
the Haakonian told me
when he traded her.
I blamed his wild stories
on isolation sickness
and then took the
ship off his hands.
Did you ever notice
anything odd about the ship?
Odd? You could say that.
I tried turning her
into a towing vessel.
She was cooperative at first,
but then she began
to require constant...
( gasps )
I hope you haven't
forgotten me.
Mr. Abaddon?
Wh-where was I?
Constant repairs.
Right. Please...
I wasn't going
to tell them anything.
Who are you speaking to?
No one. I-I-I have
to leave now.
I'll return the items
you traded for the ship.
Leave me alone.
I did what you told me.
I found you a pilot.
What is it-- what
are you seeing?
It's her.
She's right
in front of me.
CHAKOTAY:
There's no one there.
Transport me back now.
( groaning )
Janeway to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency.
He suffered a
cerebral hemorrhage.
Fortunately, I was able
to repair the damage in time.
What caused it?
It appears
his neural pathways
were recently
restructured.
I detected
a neurogenic signature.
Looks like Alice
got to him, too.
Wake him.
Oh. She was here.
The woman you saw
was an hallucination
created by the derelict ship's
neurogenic interface.
I've given you
a cortical suppressant.
She won't be
bothering you anymore.
Tell me, what does
this ship want
with our crewman?
She can't fly herself.
She needs a pilot--
a biological entity
to work in tandem
with her programming.
Well, if all she
needed was a pilot,
why didn't she
just recruit you?
I wasn't compatible.
She... said my reflexes
were too slow,
that I was as useless
as the junk that I traded,
that I couldn't get her
to where she needed to go.
Don't ask me
for the coordinates.
She never told me.
Just insisted that
I get her a real pilot.
I'm sorry I didn't
warn you before.
I couldn't resist her.
Seven of Nine
to Captain Janeway.
Please report to Astrometrics.
I've managed
to reconstruct the data
Ensign Paris was working on.
My suspicion was correct.
It is a course trajectory.
Let's see it.
It terminates
in Spatial Grid 867.
Looks uninhabited.
It's empty space
with the exception
of a small anomaly.
JANEWAY:
A particle fountain.
The Federation lost
more than a dozen ships
examining a similar phenomenon
in the Alpha Quadrant.
Relay the coordinates
to the Bridge.
Take us out of warp.
Can you see it now?
Yes.
What is it?
Home.
Distance?
Six million kilometers.
Decrease speed to
one-quarter impulse.
Full power to shields.
I'm detecting a vessel
off our starboard bow.
It's Tom.
He's headed right
for the anomaly.
Can you get a transporter lock?
KIM: No, ma'am, not
with those multiphasic
shields in place.
Are we in hailing range?
Opening a channel.
He's responding.
PARIS:
Keep your distance, Captain,
or we'll open fire.
Tom, listen to me.
The neurogenic interface
is affecting your judgment.
Drop your shields
and let us beam you aboard.
Ignore them.
Keep going.
He's not responding.
Target his propulsion systems
and fire.
( screaming )
TUVOK:
Direct hit.
The vessel's shields
are holding.
Doctor to the Bridge.
Cease fire.
Ensign Paris' neural readings
are fluctuating.
His synaptic functions
have become linked to the ship.
If we keep firing,
we could injure him
severely.
Acknowledged.
Tuvok, stand down.
We've got ten minutes
until he reaches
the particle fountain.
Is there any way
to disable their shields
without firing weapons?
If I could access
their main computer
and transmit
a shutdown sequence...
Problem is, Tom and Alice
would detect it.
They'd compensate.
Unless we find a way
to distract them.
Bridge to the Doctor.
Go ahead.
Any progress on your analysis
of the neurogenic interface?
Not yet, Captain.
Would it be possible to
tap into the interface
using a com signal?
I believe so, but I don't know
what that would accomplish.
You've got five
minutes; do it.
And tell B'Elanna to prepare
for an away mission.
Captain?
We're four minutes away.
Bridge to Sick Bay. Status?
Stand by, Captain. I'm making
the final adjustments.
I'm not sure how
I feel about getting
inside Tom's head.
Maybe you'll be able
to explain a few things
when you get back.
I knew you were
the one.
No one's ever gotten me
this close before.
I'll have you home
in just a few minutes.
I promise you won't
be disappointed.
Don't believe her.
Where's Alice?
There is no Alice.
She's a pile of circuits
in this ship's computer core.
You're letting
a program delude you.
Doctor to Bridge.
She's in.
Now.
Accessing their main computer.
You don't understand.
This is what I've
always dreamed of.
You're still dreaming,
and when you wake up,
you're in for a big surprise.
Alice needs me.
So do I.
Nice sentiment,
but it's a lie.
Your family will do anything
to keep us apart.
Don't listen to them.
Tom, it's me, B'Elanna.
Alice is an illusion.
I'm giving you
what you always wanted--
something they could never do.
Does that sound
like an illusion?
I can't... think.
Leave me alone,
both of you.
They've accessed our systems.
They're trying
to disable my shields.
Stop them.
Focus on me.
Listen to me.
My shields are failing.
Do something!
It's time to come home.
Tom.
No!
Hang on. We're going
to get you out of here.
Tom!
No!
( gasps )
I've got it, Captain.
Their shields are down.
Beam him to Sick Bay.
There's too much
interference
from the particle
fountain.
I'm boosting
the confinement beam.
Try it now.
We've got him!
Alice is losing
helm control.
Resume course to
the Alpha Quadrant.
You'll need a few days
to fully recover.
Think you can manage
to stay off your feet
for that long?
If he doesn't,
I'll break his legs.
Well, then, I'll leave you
to B'Elanna's tender mercies.
I've got something
for you.
It's a get well card
from Naomi Wildman.
It's a pretty good
likeness of you,
but I don't think
she quite captured my eyes.
I'm sorry...
for everything.
It wasn't your fault.
But I remember
all of it...
everything I said,
everything I did...
( sighs ):
It was like I was
sleepwalking.
The important thing
is you woke up.
Yeah.
Thanks for being
my alarm clock.
Anytime.
( sighs ):
From now on...
I promise no more affairs
with strange ships.
What about
the Delta Flyer?
We're just friends.