NEELIX:
Ambassador's Log,
Stardate 53263.2.
Though helpful during
my negotiations
on the Kesat homeworld,
Commander Tuvok certainly
hasn't been the most sociable
of travel companions.
Mr. Neelix.
Sorry.
How about a game
of "Species, Starship
or Anomaly"?
Surely you could find
something more productive
to occupy your time.
Come on, Tuvok.
It'll be fun.
You think of something--
species, anomaly or starship--
and I have 15 questions
to guess what it is.
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
I would prefer
some peace and quiet.
How about a riddle?
Mr. Neelix.
Come on!
Ha. It'll be fun.
I have no desire
for fun.
Okay, forget fun.
A good riddle can
stimulate the mind.
Now, no self-respecting
Vulcan can say no to that.
( sighs ):
Very well.
One riddle.
Okay, here goes.
A lone Ensign finds
himself stranded
on a Class-L planetoid
with no rations.
His only possession...
a calendar.
When Starfleet finds
him 12 months later,
he's in perfect health.
Why didn't he
starve to death?
It is a theoretical possibility
that such planetoids contain
hot water springs,
which could sustain the man
for several weeks.
Ooh, but not for
a whole year.
I concur.
Logic dictates
that the Ensign
in question would perish.
Aha!
( laughs )
Ha! I stumped you.
As a matter of fact,
he not only survived,
but his belly was full.
Why? Because he feasted
on "dates" from the calendar.
Your answer is merely wordplay.
It has no basis in reality.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Where are you going?
To find some peace and quiet.
Have fun.
( console beeping )
Tuvok to Neelix.
Miss me already, Commander?
Did you activate
the aft tactical station?
No.
Why?
There appears to be
a download in progress.
That's odd.
I'm detecting
anomalous readings.
What sort of readings?
I'm not certain, but I believe
it's a cloaking frequency
that consists...
( groaning )
( static )
Commander?
Tuvok!
Delta Flyer to Voyager.
Mayday!
( grunting )
Tuvok, what happened?
Report.
He's in neuroleptic shock.
I'll need another
20 milligrams of synaptizine.
I'll get it.
It's not working.
I'll need to try
direct cortical stimulation.
Initiate a neurostatic
pulse on my mark.
Right.
( grunting )
Now!
( pulsing sound )
Again!
( sighs ):
His vital signs have stabilized
for the moment, anyway.
But he suffered severe
neurological trauma.
Do you know
what caused it?
Some kind of
alien weapon.
NEELIX:
By the time
I reached Tuvok,
whoever had attacked him
was gone.
What about
the surrounding space?
Any indication
of cloaked vessels?
Between trying to tend
to the Commander
and piloting the Flyer,
I had my hands full.
I... I didn't think
to scan for cloaked ships.
I'm sorry.
You saved Tuvok's life,
Neelix.
You have nothing
to be sorry about.
How do you plan
to treat him?
I won't know until
I've run a series of
neurological scans.
But it would
certainly help
to know something
about the weapon.
Neelix, these Kesat
you were negotiating with...
any reason to believe they
might know something about this?
It couldn't
hurt to ask.
Time to reopen
diplomatic channels.
Deputy Investigator Naroq,
Kesat Security.
Captain Janeway,
Commander Chakotay,
Ambassador Neelix.
You've done
your homework.
I familiarized myself
with the facts
on the way here.
We're hoping you can help us
shed some light
on what happened
to our crewman.
I believe I can.
Based on the information
you provided,
it is my opinion that he was
a victim of the Ba'Neth.
I've never heard of them.
NAROQ: I'm not surprised.
In my language, their name
means "shadow people."
They're a species
obsessed with concealing
their identity--
extremely paranoid
and xenophobic.
Well, that explains
their cloaking technology.
It's my belief
they've been responsible
for several unexplained attacks
similar to this one.
Why wasn't I
warned about them
during my negotiations
with your government?
Because my government's
official position
is that
the Ba'Neth do not exist.
Most people think
they're a myth.
There's nothing mythical about
what happened to Mr. Tuvok.
Why is your government
so skeptical?
Because there have been
so few encounters
with the Ba'Neth.
And, well, no one's ever
actually seen one.
How many encounters
are we talking about exactly?
Before this incident, 12.
I guess we're lucky 13.
You're lucky
I gave my supervisor
two bottles of Kesatian ale
to get this assignment.
Any other inspector would have
simply attributed
Commander Tuvok's injuries
to "unexplained phenomena."
No offense, Mr. Naroq,
but what makes you so sure
the Ba'Neth aren't just a myth?
This incident fits
the pattern, Captain.
All of the alleged encounters
have occurred aboard vessels
foreign to this sector.
I believe they've been
attempts by the Ba'Neth
to assess the technology
of new arrivals.
They were trying to
download tactical data.
And Commander Tuvok suffered
severe neural damage.
That's also consistent
with previous attacks.
The Ba'Neth were making sure
he would not tell anyone
what he saw.
Maybe that's why Tuvok's
tricorder was destroyed.
They didn't want us to see
the cloaking frequency
he'd found.
He found a cloaking frequency?
Apparently.
Captain, I don't blame you
for finding my theories
a bit eccentric.
I'm used to it.
It's why I'm still
a deputy investigator.
But I've brought equipment
to help your investigation.
Let me examine Commander Tuvok
and run scans on the vessel
where he was attacked.
I may finally be able
to prove my theories.
With all due respect,
we're more interested
in saving Tuvok's life.
If we work together,
maybe we can do both.
His cognitive, memory
and logic centers
have all been
severely damaged.
But he still has
brain activity,
which is more
than I can say
for any of the
previous victims.
Vulcan neural tissue
is extremely resilient.
I have no doubt that a brain
from a lesser species
would not have survived.
If you could only
tell us what you saw,
Mr. Tuvok.
I don't think we'll be hearing
from him anytime soon.
Keep working.
I'll let you know
if we find anything
that might help.
I'll take you to see
where the attack occurred.
Something I can do
for you, Mr. Neelix?
I want to help.
Unless you have a degree
in Vulcan neurobiology
that I'm not aware of,
there's nothing you can do.
There must be something.
My advice is to return
to your quarters
and get some rest.
There's no way that I'm
going to be able to sleep
knowing that Tuvok
is lying here like this.
There have been rare cases
in which comatose patients
responded to external stimuli:
aromas, touch, voices.
So... you're saying
that if I stay here
and, and try to talk to Tuvok,
I might be able
to provoke some sort
of response.
If anyone can provoke Tuvok,
Mr. Neelix, it's you.
Good morning, Tuvok!
I brought you a few more
items from your quarters
to help liven up
Sick Bay.
Your kal-toh game,
in case you decide
you're ready for a match.
Oh, and I also thought
that you might enjoy
a recitation
of that classic
proto-Vulcan drama,
Clash on
the Fire Plains.
I'll be performing
all 23 parts myself.
Uh, I also brought
you some flowers
from Airponics Bay.
Oh, that's fragrant, isn't it?
Uh, perhaps you'd enjoy
some Vulcan incense.
Now, how about some music?
Computer, access
Vulcan audio file,
selection 56-Alpha.
( voices chanting atonally )
Mr. Neelix, what is
that dreadful noise?
The Chants of the Monks
of T'Panit.
Personally, I think
it's dreadful, too,
but it's one of
Tuvok's favorites.
I appreciate
your efforts, Mr. Neelix,
but I'm trying to analyze
his latest
neurological scans,
and this music
is very distracting.
You said I was
supposed to stimulate
his senses.
I said stimulate
them, Mr. Neelix,
not annihilate them.
Computer, pause music.
( sighs ):
Thank you.
Doctor.
Tuvok!
You've had an accident.
You're in Sick Bay.
Relax, Commander,
I only want to scan you.
NEELIX:
Don't worry, Tuvok.
He's only trying
to help you.
It's only a tricorder.
See?
I-it won't hurt you.
Now try it.
( quietly ):
Well done, Mr. Neelix.
Commander Chakotay says
you've found something.
That, Captain,
is an understatement.
Listen.
( chirping )
What is it?
The sound of history
being made.
Less poetry, Mr. Naroq,
more facts.
The sound you're hearing
indicates the presence
of veridium isotopes.
Residual particles
from the Ba'Neths'
cloaking field.
You've detected
these isotopes before?
Yes, but only
after they've decayed.
You see, veridium has
a very brief half-life--
less than 70 hours.
The previous sites I've
studied have been months,
sometimes years old!
But these isotopes
are still active.
We can use Mr. Naroq's
photolitic converter
to illuminate them.
So you see, Captain,
why this is an historic moment?
We may finally learn
what the Ba'Neth look like.
Well, let's see
what we've got.
You don't know how long
I've waited to meet you.
So, the Ba'Neth aren't a myth
after all.
This is the clearest image
ever captured!
Perhaps.
I believe I can adjust
our internal sensors
to improve it.
What are you doing?
What are you...
You might disrupt
the image entirely.
Tentacles!
I always suspected
they were multipeds.
Doctor to the Captain.
Please report to Sick Bay.
I'm on my way.
Seven...
if we can integrate
Mr. Naroq's
photolitic technology
into the deflector array,
we might be able to de-cloak
a Ba'Neth ship.
The technology only
works at close range.
We have to find
the ship before
we can expose it.
We still need that
cloaking frequency.
One step at a time.
DOCTOR:
The Vulcan brain--
a puzzle
wrapped inside an enigma,
housed inside a cranium.
Tuvok's neural pathways
have begun to bypass
the damaged tissue.
They're forming
new synaptic connections.
In effect, his brain
is rewiring itself.
Whether this is due
to my neurostatic therapy
or Neelix's
rehabilitation regimen
or some combination of the two,
I can't be certain.
Is there any chance he'll
make a full recovery?
It's much too soon to say,
but he's alert
and he's already regained
his basic motor skills.
But still no speech.
NEELIX:
It's only a matter
of time, Captain.
Look how far
he's come already.
I hope you're right, Neelix.
But if he could talk,
he might be able
to tell us something about
that cloaking frequency.
We're not sure
how much he recalls.
For that matter,
we're not certain
he recognizes any of us
or even knows who he is.
I'm going to take him
on a tour of the ship.
The Doctor thinks that
familiar sights and sounds
might get the old
synaptic juices flowing.
Don't worry, Captain.
Tuvok will be back
to his old self
before you can say,
"live long and prosper."
I've brought a visitor.
CHAKOTAY:
Good to see you
up and around.
You remember
Commander Chakotay.
We were just running
a shield diagnostic.
Would you like
to take a look?
This is Tactical Station,
where you work.
Just keeping it
warm for you.
Hope you don't mind.
That's the shield array.
This controls
the tractor emitters.
I think he remembers it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You just activated
the photon torpedo banks.
That's all
right, Tuvok.
Everybody
makes mistakes.
We'll be back later.
Last... but not least...
your quarters.
You spend a lot
of time here,
reading...
meditating...
Mr. Paris once
referred to it
as the "Vulcan Vault."
( chuckles )
Ahh...
Well, look around, explore.
Astrometrics to the Bridge.
Mr. Naroq and I
have completed our
deflector modifications.
We're ready
to test the array.
Stand by. Reduce speed
to one-quarter impulse.
Harry, full power
to the deflector array.
KIM:
Aye.
All right, Seven...
do it.
Activating the deflector.
I'd call that
a pretty successful test.
They've been watching
us all along.
Hail them.
Which one?
There's practically
a fleet out there.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Federation
Starship Voyager.
We intend you no harm.
They're charging weapons.
Shields.
They're scrambling, Captain,
in all directions.
Follow the lead vessel.
( crying out )
It's okay, Tuvok.
I'm here with you.
Everything is going
to be all right.
You're safe with me.
Still no response
to our hails.
I hate to ruin a good chase,
but the Ba'Neth ship
is moving out of
the deflector's range.
Seven, can you get
their cloaking frequency?
They're blocking our scans.
We've lost them.
They're gone now, Tuvok.
I told you you'd be safe.
Yes...
you did.
Tuvok?
What?
Tell me, what did I do?
You told me...
I wouldn't be hurt.
Do you know who I am?
You are Neelix.
I'm safe... with you.
We need Tuvok to tell us
anything he can remember
about the attack.
Captain, he may be
talking again,
but that doesn't mean
he's ready to be interrogated.
He's beginning
to experience emotions--
volatile ones.
During this last encounter with
the Ba'Neth, he was terrified.
We'll tread lightly,
I promise.
All right, Tuvok,
you can come in now.
It's nice to see you.
Captain Janeway.
That's right.
This is Mr. Naroq.
Please sit down.
Two days ago, you
were aboard a shuttle
with Mr. Neelix.
You detected
a cloaked intruder.
He attacked you.
Yes...
th-that's why I'm having
difficulty now.
Yes, and in order
to help you,
we have to find
the people who hurt you.
Before the intruder
injured you,
you managed to scan
him with this.
You recorded his
cloaking frequency,
but the tricorder
was damaged
and the information
was lost.
Can you tell us anything
about that frequency?
Try to remember.
I was scanning.
That's right.
What did you see?
I... I don't remember.
Try!
JANEWAY: All right,
that's enough.
We're done for now.
But, Captain...
Join Seven of Nine
in Astrometrics.
See if she's made any progress
with the Ba'Neth.
Well, uh, we should
be going, too.
A few of the crew have
offered to help with
Tuvok's rehabilitation.
I thought we might have lunch
later, just the two of us.
I prefer to stay with Neelix.
Oh, Tuvok... I'm-I'm sure
that you would...
It's all right.
You two go ahead.
I have a lot of work
to do anyway.
Oh...
The object of the game
is to turn this
jumble of rods
into a perfect sphere.
We take turns
positioning our pieces.
Whoever gets the shape
to appear first wins.
I like the way it looks now.
( chuckling )
What do you say
we give it a try?
This has always been one
of your favorite games, Tuvok.
It helps keep
your logic sharp.
I'll go first.
Now you.
Go ahead.
I don't like this game.
When you first taught me
how to play,
I wasn't very good, either,
but you kept encouraging me
and pretty soon, I scored
my first kal-toh.
It just takes
practice,
that's all.
Try again.
You can do it.
I don't like this game!
The Doctor helped me access
my personnel file.
NEELIX:
Nice picture.
You should see mine.
It's awful.
I was an instructor
at Starfleet Academy.
I've received
17 commendations
for valor.
I'm a husband...
a father.
You're an extraordinary fellow,
Tuvok.
I was
an extraordinary fellow.
You're still the same person.
Then why do I no longer work
on the Bridge?
We talked about that.
You had an accident.
And now I'm not smart enough.
Tuvok, you've just
got to be patient.
Look how much progress
you've made already.
He... could dismantle
a photonic warhead
in... in less than
30 seconds.
I can't even play kal-toh.
It's going to take time,
but you'll relearn
all those things.
How do you know that?
Well, because the Doctor...
The Doctor?
The Doctor doesn't know
how to make me better!
Does he?
Well, not yet, but...
I'll never be him again!
You don't know that.
The Vulcan mind...
I'm not a Vulcan!
Not anymore!
( angry grunting )
What's going on?
It's okay, Doctor.
I can handle this.
Please, Tuvok,
try to relax.
Everything's
going to be fine.
No! Nothing's fine!
Get away from me!
You'd better go.
Now, Mr. Neelix!
I'll take it from here.
Oh, sorry;
I didn't mean to interrupt.
You didn't.
Yes, I did.
You were pondering...
something difficult,
by the looks of it.
Anything I can help you with?
Unlikely.
Try me.
How do you find something
that's invisible?
The Ba'Neth.
We have the ability
to illuminate them,
but to do so,
we must first locate them,
which we cannot accomplish
without their
cloaking frequency.
That's quite a riddle.
One that we might
be able to solve
if Commander Tuvok could tell us
what he saw.
How is his
rehabilitation
progressing?
Well, I thought
it was going great, but now...
let's just say that I've got
a riddle of my own.
Try me.
All right.
When is a Vulcan
no longer a Vulcan?
When his genetic code
is sufficiently altered.
No. I-I-I was speaking
metaphorically.
In that case, a person
is no longer Vulcan
when he's lost his logic.
Right! And how
does he get it back?
He must be taught.
Exactly, but what
if he's brain damaged
and emotionally
unstable?
How does he learn?
It may be impossible
for him to learn
what you're trying
to teach.
Well, thanks
for the pep talk.
I was merely suggesting
that you adapt to
the circumstances.
What circumstances?!
Are you saying that the,
the Tuvok I know is gone--
that I should stop
trying to help him?
When I was separated
from the collective,
I, too, was damaged.
I was no longer connected
to the hive mind.
I lost many abilities that
I had acquired as a drone,
but I adapted.
Because Captain Janeway
didn't give up on you.
She kept trying to help you.
But not by restoring me
to what I'd been--
by helping me discover
what I could become.
What are you making?
A flower.
It's for you.
Thank you.
I'm not sure
I deserve a gift.
I shouldn't have
shouted at you.
I was angry.
I'm sorry.
You were frustrated.
I don't blame you.
I'm the one who
should be apologizing.
Why?
Because I was pushing
you too hard.
I was trying to mold you
into something you weren't.
You were disappointed in me
because I can't
do anything as well
as I did before.
Maybe there are things
that you can do better.
What can I do better?
Well... this, for example.
You would've
considered it
an "illogical use
of your time."
It's not good.
No, it's wonderful.
It's... creative.
It's a symbol of friendship.
Before your accident,
you never would
have considered
that my feelings
might have been hurt.
You, you would have certainly
never have made me a gift.
We weren't friends?
Well, uh...
we were colleagues,
and I certainly felt affection
for you.
But I didn't return
those feelings.
You... tolerated me.
I don't understand.
You said things like
( imitating Tuvok ):
"Mr. Neelix, please contain
your exuberance."
And, uh, "Mr. Neelix,
I have no desire for fun."
( both laughing )
And you never smiled.
You got a much better
sense of humor now.
I like to smile.
Me, too.
I don't want to play
kal-toh anymore...
or-or meditate...
or... work on
logic problems.
You don't have to.
What can we do instead?
Whatever you want.
Teach me things
that you like to do.
Here we are--
a triple-chocolate
wikki fruit sundae
with warm fettran sauce.
Fettran sauce on...
a sundae?
Wait till you taste it.
And you really made this?
As Neelix says,
dig in.
Mmm... this is great.
This is
fantastic.
What did I tell you?
Tuvok has a
flair for food.
All morning, he's been
creating new recipes,
using combinations
of ingredients
that I, I never would
have imagined.
For example...
a terra nut soufflé...
Jimbalian fudge cake
with peppermint coulis...
sweet leola root tart.
Mmm!
Only desserts?
How come?
They taste good.
Ha!
Yeah, you better watch out,
Neelix. Tuvok may put you
out of a job.
From your mouth to
the Captain's ears.
She must have heard me.
( both laugh )
What's all this?
We're having fun.
Uh, turns out Tuvok is
quite the pastry chef.
Would you like
some terra-nut
soufflé, Captain?
Oh, I'd love some.
Thank you.
Oh...
that is delicious.
I'm pleased that
you like it.
What are you
making now?
Pistachio cake with
parra cream sauce.
Oh, parra cream's
my favorite.
Then you'll have
the first piece.
Tuvok, have you
remembered anything more
about what happened
on the Flyer?
I detected
a cloaking frequency.
Yes, that's right.
Can you describe it?
I don't know, I, I...
Did it have
a symmetric modulation?
Was the amplitude
constant?
I-I don't understand.
It's all right.
I don't mean
to push you, Tuvok,
but maybe if we could...
It's difficult for him,
Captain.
Maybe you can try again
tomorrow.
This...
This is what I saw.
What is it?
A cloaking frequency.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The computer has analyzed
Tuvok's diagram
and identified
the Ba'Neth cloaking
frequency.
We've narrowed the search
to a handful of systems.
Here we go, Captain.
A nine-million terawatt
cloaking field in Grid 216.
Nine million terawatts.
Whatever they're hiding,
it's huge.
Alter course, Mr. Paris.
PARIS:
Yes, ma'am.
Bridge to Astrometrics.
Status.
SEVEN:
The deflector array
is ready, Captain.
Raise shields.
Aye, Captain.
PARIS:
We're within range.
All right, Seven...
light them up.
KIM:
It's an armed outpost.
Approximately
3,000 life signs, 22 ships.
Hail them.
No response, Captain.
They're charging weapons.
Open a channel,
all subspace bands.
They're firing.
Cease fire immediately...
or I'll transmit
the coordinates of this outpost
to the Kesat homeworld.
That got their attention.
Several days ago,
a member of your species
attacked one of my crewmen.
He was badly injured.
In order to treat him,
I need to know more
about the weapon that was used.
They're responding.
Audio only.
We do not share technology.
But you take it from others.
The attacker was downloading
our tactical database
when the incident occurred.
We must assess
potential threats.
Paranoid,
just as I predicted.
In exchange for information
about your weapon,
we'll provide you
with tactical data
on several species
we've recently encountered.
You can assess their
potential threats all you want.
The Kesat investigator
aboard your vessel
cannot be trusted.
You know about me?
You have been attempting
to expose us for years.
You are a threat.
You must be stopped.
They're charging
weapons again.
Wait.
It was
my photolitic converter
that allowed Voyager
to de-cloak you.
If you give Captain Janeway
what she wants,
I'll give you the converter.
You can use it
to adapt your technology
so ours can no longer
expose you.
I doubt you'll get
as enticing an offer
from the Kesat homeworld.
It would be a shame
if you forced me to hail them.
We have an agreement.
( mid-tempo jazz playing )
( door chimes )
Enter.
What are you listening to?
A selection
from Tom's jazz database--
it really swings.
( laughing )
Computer, pause the music.
I've been reviewing
the holodeck files.
I wish to visit the Risa
Water Recreation Park.
Will you accompany me?
Maybe after
your doctor's appointment.
Appointment?
The Doctor's analyzed
the Ba'Neth weapon,
and he's devised
a procedure to treat you.
You... you should be
proud of yourself.
I-if you hadn't drawn
that picture on the cake,
we may never have found
a treatment.
I wish I never
drew that picture.
Why?
Because I don't wish
to undergo the procedure.
You're having
preoperative jitters.
That's all.
Don't worry.
Everyone gets them.
Just think about it.
In a few hours,
you'll be yourself again.
I am myself.
But... you'll be able
to do all the things
that you used to do--
work on the Bridge,
advise the Captain.
I want to be
able to have fun.
With you.
I won't be able to.
Will I?
Well...
you won't call it fun.
You'll call it
"deriving satisfaction,"
but it's basically
the same thing.
You'll still
experience emotions.
But I won't express them.
Probably not.
Then how will you know
how much I enjoy being with you?
You've just told me.
We'll still be friends?
Of course.
Even if I...
merely tolerate you?
I'd be lying if I told you
that things between us
will stay the same.
Well, then, why?
Why do you want me to go back
to the way I was?
Because this crew needs
its Tactical Officer
on the Bridge,
and I wouldn't be
a very good friend
if I ignored that just so
that you'd be nicer to me.
Mr. Tuvok, I
was beginning
to think you
weren't coming.
I was experiencing
preoperative jitters.
Neelix helped me
overcome them.
Glad to hear it.
Now, please
lie down.
I'll see you
after the procedure?
Of course.
I'm going to miss him.
Me, too.
Hello, Commander.
Mr. Neelix.
It's good to see
you up and about.
Are you feeling better?
The Doctor has approved
my return to duty.
That's wonderful news.
How about a celebratory
glass of champagne?
Tea will suffice.
Of course.
I'm preparing
a special dinner tonight,
in honor of your recovery.
I don't suppose
that you'd be interested
in preparing one
of your famous desserts.
I have much more important
things to do
than engage in the preparation
of nutritionally
deficient foods.
Maybe another time.
Sundays.
I beg your pardon?
I have given
further consideration
to your riddle
regarding the Ensign
who survived
by consuming the "dates"
from his calendar.
It occurs to me
that he could also have eaten
the "Sundays."
That's a very clever answer,
Mr. Vulcan.
But it's not very logical,
is it?
No.
It's not.