Gedrin!
( coughing )
What happened?
I lost you.
37 bio-pods were damaged.
I had to disconnect them
from the reactor.
Were they dead?
I had no choice.
( both cough )
The main power's holding.
The rest of the
bio-pods are secure,
and that leaves us.
Don't look so worried.
It'll be like a simple
night's sleep.
( loud rumbling )
( gasps )
We're out of time.
Do you think we'll dream?
I don't know.
We'll get through this.
What if there's
nothing left?
We'll start again.
Five years.
( beeping )
( gasps )
Report.
We've entered some kind
of a subspace corridor.
We were cruising
at warp 6, then, wham.
This thing pulled at our
warp field like a magnet.
JANEWAY:
Where did that debris come from?
Unknown, but the corridor
is filled with it.
Metal fragments, plasma exhaust,
organic residue.
Some of the debris
is over 800 years old, Captain.
I'd like to avoid
becoming part of
this garbage stream.
Can you find a way out?
I don't know.
There's hundreds
of corridors.
It's like a maze.
Well, be a good rat and
find us the cheese, hmm?
I'll do my best, Captain.
Tuvok?
It was a vessel, sir.
They are hailing us.
Put it through.
Who are you?
I'm Captain Kathryn Janeway
of the Starship Voyager
and you are...?
This under-space belongs to us.
We're here by accident.
We're trying to find a way out.
Can you help us?
Help you?
Yes. We'll help you.
They are targeting our shields
with a resonance pulse.
It's altering the harmonics.
We're being pushed
out of the corridor.
( rumbling )
We're clear.
The vessel has exited
the corridor as well.
Captain, we're over
200 light-years
from where we entered
the corridor.
200 light-years in five minutes?
Hail them.
Thank you for your help.
There's something
I'd like to ask you.
We've got a long
journey ahead of us,
and I was wondering
if we could negotiate
passage through
this under-space of yours.
Lower your shields.
Prepare to be boarded.
Boarded? For what reason?
We must purge your computer.
Remove all readings you've
gathered in our territory.
We pose no threat to you.
We're simply trying to...
We're going to destroy
that information
one way or another.
Lower your shields.
I won't do that.
Evasive maneuvers.
Try to
disable them.
Their vessel is
highly maneuverable.
It's difficult to get
a phaser lock.
Picking up two more ships
heading our way.
Direct hit. Our warp
drive is off-line.
Shields down to 82 percent.
60 percent.
They're closing.
We could use some
clever suggestions
about now.
There's a planet
eight million
kilometers ahead--
uninhabited--
but the atmosphere
is charged
with radiogenic particles.
How radiogenic?
3,000 isorems.
If we route enough power
to the shields,
we can survive in that,
but maybe
our friends can't.
Shields at 53 percent.
Do it.
Entering
the thermosphere.
Radiation levels at 3,000
isorems and climbing.
CHAKOTAY:
The alien ships?
TUVOK: In pursuit
and charging weapons.
Increase our
descent vector.
They're still closing.
Direct hit to our aft shields.
Find the highest
concentration of radiation,
and take us through it.
Proximity radiation
at 4,000 isorems...
5,000...
Six.
Their shields are weakening.
They're breaking off.
Now... all we need
is a place to set down
and make repairs. Tom?
We're clearing
the lower stratosphere.
On screen.
I thought you said
this planet was uninhabited.
The radiation must have
interfered with my scans.
I doubt it's inhabited anymore.
Looks like this planet
is in the middle
of a nuclear winter.
Agreed. Gamma radiation levels
are highly toxic.
The impact crater suggests
an orbital bombardment.
How long ago?
From the rate of radiogenic
decay... 892 years.
This must have been
a city of millions.
Set us down.
Disengaging engines.
Stand down Red Alert.
Assign damage repair teams,
and, Tom, make sure B'Elanna
has enough help in Engineering.
I want those warp
engines back on line.
Yes, ma'am.
Our "friends"
are still in orbit.
Circling like vultures.
Well, they're going
to go hungry.
Not if they find a way
to adapt their shields
and come down after us.
Captain... I'm detecting
faint life signs
coming from a chamber
several hundred meters
beneath the surface.
Survivors?
After 900 years?
Oversee the repair teams.
You're going down there?
If somebody survived
this catastrophe,
they might need our help.
Get a good fix
on those coordinates.
I don't want to beam
into solid rock.
Seven, Tuvok, you're with me.
These walls have been reinforced
with tritonium.
They built this place to last.
Most of the power relays
are still active.
Not bad
after nine centuries.
The main reactor
is drawing energy
from the planet's
geothermal core.
Efficient.
Some kind
of stasis pod.
( computer beeping )
This display indicates
that there are more chambers
behind these walls.
Some of them have failed.
It's amazing
they survived at all.
Let's see what else we can find.
Seven?
What are
you doing?
I've activated
the reanimation sequence.
He may be able to
provide us with answers.
We don't know anything
about this species.
They could be hostile.
Most humanoid cultures are.
Remind me to reacquaint you
with away mission protocols.
Who?
It's all right.
We're not your enemy.
We're from a starship.
We discovered
this chamber
and revived you.
How long was I...?
In stasis?
Close to 900 years.
900?
Jisa.
Help her, please.
No, Jisa.
She was my wife.
I won't hurt you.
I was drifting in and out
of consciousness when
they brought me here,
but I thought I saw you
appear out of thin air.
I'm a computer program,
a hologram.
And the others?
Flesh and blood,
like yourself.
You're the ones
that took me
out of stasis.
I don't recognize
your species.
Human. Our home planet
is halfway across the galaxy.
And you've expanded
your territory
into this space?
Our ship was
brought here by accident.
We're trying to get home.
You're Borg.
How do you know that?
Don't you recognize
my people, the Vaadwaur?
The collective's memory
from 900 years ago
is fragmentary.
I've had many encounters
with your kind.
And lived
to tell about them?
Impressive.
How did you find us?
We needed someplace
to hide from the Turei,
after they found us in one
of their subspace corridors.
Their corridors?
So they claimed.
The corridors were ours.
It took centuries
to map them.
We were the envy
of a hundred species,
including the Turei.
Are they responsible
for what happened
to your planet?
The Turei and
a dozen others.
What one couldn't
accomplish,
the others finally did.
I... would like to look
at what's left of my world.
We made our
final stand there.
I've scanned the caverns.
You've got a thousand more
stasis pods down there--
most of them still active.
Hundreds of ships,
land vehicles... weapons.
A single battalion
and their families.
We had planned to
come out of stasis
after five years.
We believed that by then,
the alliance would have been
at each other's throats.
You were going to rebuild?
No, not here.
We knew this planet
would be poisoned
for centuries.
We were planning
to go to another world,
start a colony,
hope to find new allies,
learn from them.
Your power core is
still functioning.
It was the controls
that were damaged
in the attack.
That's why you never
came out of stasis.
Jisa and I
lived there
in the old quarter.
We had a garden
overlooking the street below.
It's a shame
she didn't show
more courage
at the end.
Given the circumstances...
Well, that's no excuse.
Pardon me
for saying this,
but that seems
a bit heartless.
When it rains,
do you run from
doorway to doorway,
trying to stay dry,
getting wet all the while,
or do you just accept
the fact that it's raining
and walk with dignity?
Rain's one thing.
Plasma bombs are
something else.
But the principle is the same.
I'd bring an umbrella.
Maybe it's not too late
to meet a new ally
and learn from her.
I took the liberty
of preparing a large assortment
of Delta Quadrant dishes.
Hopefully, there's something
here that you'll like.
You're Talax-ilzay.
Talaxian, but you're right.
My ancestors referred
to themselves as Talax-ilzay
in the Old Tongue.
The Old Tongue was new
when I met your race.
You traveled
all the way to Talaxia?
And farther.
Our corridors took us
to many worlds.
I'm curious.
Have you heard of us,
the Vaadwaur?
Oh, I'm afraid there aren't
many records from that period,
but Vaadwaur is a word
in the Old Tongue.
It means, uh, "foolish."
I'm, uh, I'm sure that it's, uh,
just a coincidence, of course.
I... I didn't mean to be rude.
Your ancestors were wise.
Only fools would let
this happen to them.
Chakotay to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead.
Looks like our friends in orbit
have found us.
We're on our way.
Report.
Six Turei vessels
are in orbit,
all firing
plasma charges.
That was 2,000 meters
to starboard.
KIM: Looks like they
can't get an exact fix
on our position.
The radiogenic atmosphere
must be disrupting
their targeting.
TUVOK: 900 meters.
PARIS: They're getting closer.
JANEWAY:
Can we return fire?
CHAKOTAY: We have
the same problem.
Our torpedoes
won't lock on.
TUVOK:
Direct hit.
Aft shields down to 18 percent.
Captain, can you
transmit a signal
through this atmosphere?
We've already tried
talking to them.
I have no intention of
speaking with the Turei.
We put a sentry
satellite in orbit
directly above
the city.
You could use
its sensors
to help guide
your torpedoes.
It's there,
intact and functional.
GEDRIN:
Open a channel.
I'll give you
the activation code.
I'm a few centuries out of date.
You can enter
the activation code here.
It's processing
our telemetry.
Triangulate.
Fire.
Direct hit.
The lead ship
has lost shields.
Its propulsion
is down.
One more torpedo
will finish them.
The other ships are retreating.
Captain, why don't you
keep firing?
We've scared them off.
That's enough for now.
But they'll come back
with twice as many ships.
With any luck,
our warp drive will be
back on line by then.
The Turei may
be cowards,
but their technology has become
much more advanced than ours.
If you leave us,
we will be slaughtered again.
What do you propose?
Help us off this planet,
and we will show you
subspace corridors
known to nobody else.
You will be free from the Turei,
and you will be
a thousand light-years
closer to your home.
Let's wake up
your battalion.
Dragon's teeth.
JANEWAY:
"Dragon's teeth"?
An old Greek myth.
After a dragon
was killed in a war,
its teeth were spread out
over the battlefield.
They took root,
and warriors sprung
from the ground
to continue the fighting.
Captain's Log,
supplemental.
We've revived
nearly 200 of the Vaadwaur,
and we're moving forward
with our unexpected alliance.
Voyager  was pulled
into the corridor,
200 light-years from here.
Pulled in?
There must have been a break
along the radial wall.
The corridors occur
naturally, but they're
very unstable.
They're
damaged by use.
Obviously, the Turei
don't have the wisdom
to maintain them properly.
They'll be very difficult
to navigate after
centuries of neglect.
We've only been able to chart
a few of the corridors.
Can you provide us
with a more complete map?
We've never kept
written records
for security reasons.
Of course, we've
committed all the
corridors to memory--
every multifold,
every spatial intersect.
We'll be happy to plot
a course for you,
but first, we'll need
to get past the Turei.
How many vessels
are in orbit?
Eleven.
Mr. Gaul, Tuvok, start working
on a tactical plan.
If we do manage
to escape,
we'll need to locate
a habitable world.
Seven, scan
the astrometric database.
See what you can find.
Someplace out of the way.
Yes, Captain.
Morin, take charge of reviving
the rest of our battalion.
Many of our bio-pods have
been damaged. I could
use some assistance.
JANEWAY:
Our Chief Engineer will be
glad to give you a hand.
Thank you.
Well, let's get started.
We've got a civilization
to rebuild.
No story tonight, Naomi.
I had to cook
for 200 people today.
That's okay.
I'm tired, too.
Did you get a chance
to meet any of the children?
I don't like them.
Why not?
I just don't.
Well, that's
not good enough.
I'm the ship's Ambassador.
You're the Captain's Assistant.
We have to make
a-a good impression
on our new friends.
They're not
my friends.
Well... not yet.
Listen... first thing tomorrow,
you and I will get together
with a couple
of the children...
No.
Naomi, what's wrong?
Nothing.
I don't like them,
and I don't want
to play with them.
That doesn't sound like you.
Tell me what happened.
They called
you names.
Names?
They said everybody from
your planet was stupid.
They said your
ears were funny.
They said just looking
at you made them laugh.
They said...
I-I-I... I get the idea.
Children can be
a little cruel sometimes,
but there's no need
to take it personally.
Besides, my ears are
kind of funny.
I don't want
to play with them.
Well... and you don't have to.
Okay.
Come on.
Good night.
I'll tell you
a story tomorrow, I promise.
I'm not happy with
these fluctuations.
We may be trying
to reactivate
too many ships at once.
I suggest we focus
on the assault fighters.
Qual tel t'pok.
Thanks.
When did you learn Klingon?
Just a few phrases.
I was studying
your database.
The Klingons are
a noble race.
They have their moments.
"Today is a good
day to die."
Pardon?
Kahless, your
greatest warrior.
That was his battle cry.
You seem to have
taken an interest
in Klingon history.
There are many parallels
between our cultures.
The Vaadwaur
have also learned
to embrace death
without fear.
As children, we're taught
to fall asleep each night
imagining a different
way to die.
I prefer curling up
with a good book.
Hmm.
( sighs )
Computer,
access my personal database.
COMPUTER:
Access established.
Go into the Talaxian
linguistic files,
Old Tongue dialect.
Find and define
the word "Vaadwaur."
Vaadwaur: archaic adjective.
Primary meaning: foolish.
Additional meanings:
Weak-minded, reckless, blind.
What's the first known usage?
First written example
appears
in Eldaxon's
Collected Folklore,
Second Edition.
Year of publication,
5012, New Calendar.
( sighs )
Computer,
name the specific folktales
that use the word "Vaadwaur."
"The Demon
with the Golden Voice,"
"The Tale
of the Deadly Stranger,"
"The Tale of the Boy
Who Lost His Head,"
"The Tale of the Bloody Hand."
Not exactly Mother Goose.
Computer, transfer the text
of those stories to my quarters.
Transfer complete.
That star cluster
in Grid 1421?
Nearly half the planets
are inhabitable.
Unfortunately, they
are already occupied
by the Borg.
The Borg?
In my century,
they'd only assimilated
a handful of systems.
It looks like they've
spread through the Quadrant
like a plague.
No offense.
None taken.
We had a colony near
the twin star in Grid 315.
That is part of the
Devore Imperium now.
And who are they?
An authoritarian regime.
They claim 11 systems
across three sectors.
I don't suppose they'd
be willing to negotiate
for a continent or two.
The Devore are
intolerant of outsiders.
Well, it doesn't matter.
We have nothing
to negotiate with.
Our technology is 900
years out of date.
Your pessimism
is irrelevant.
We will find a home
for you.
I hope you're right.
16 Turei vessels
are now in orbit.
Long-range sensors
indicate five more on the way.
I can understand
that they want the
odds in their favor,
but isn't
that overkill?
They may have
detected us.
If they know their history,
they'll come prepared.
900 years is a long time
to hold a grudge.
The Turei would
like nothing more
than to find the rest of
our subspace corridors.
We can't allow that
to happen.
Then I suggest
we use the element of surprise.
At 0600, Voyager
will leave the surface
and engage the Turei ships
in orbit.
As we draw their fire,
the more powerful
Vaadwaur vessels
will attack
from multiple vectors.
The rest of the Vaadwaur
will break orbit
from the opposite side
of the planet
and proceed
to the subspace corridors.
We'll rendezvous
with them afterwards.
What if  Voyager is disabled?
We'll be defenseless.
If we armed
my ships with your
photon torpedoes...
I can't authorize that.
Why not?
Starfleet protocols are
very strict about the
transfer of weapons.
I'm not used to putting my life
into someone else's hands.
There are a lot of things you're
going to have to get used to.
We've faced enemies
worse than the Turei.
I'm confident
we can handle them.
I need those weapons.
I'm sorry.
The answer's no.
If you want access
to our corridors...
We'll continue home
through open space
if we have to.
All right. Our lives
are in your hands.
We've found a planet
in a nebula
near the junction
of Corridors 39 and 875.
We'd be isolated
and relatively safe.
"Relatively"?
I'm afraid the planet
is somewhat harsh.
There are no large
bodies of water,
and the vegetation is sparse.
This is absurd!
Ensign, we need a power coupling
over here, on the double.
Our plan was
to reoccupy one of
our former colonies,
gain allies,
rebuild our forces--
take back what
was ours!
Our former colonies
are destroyed or were occupied
by species that are
far more advanced than we are.
Then we'll find a way
to take them back.
With what? A battalion
of obsolete ships
and outdated weapons?
No...
with Voyager.
I've been studying
their technology--
the control systems,
propulsion, weaponry.
We could learn to operate
the vessel ourselves.
What are you saying?
After they engage
the Turei,
they'll expect us
to assist them.
Instead, we'll attack.
We'll put as many
soldiers as we can
onto Voyager
and take it into
the corridors!
This is a mistake.
If we fail,
we'll lose everything.
If you'd like,
I can return you
to your stasis pod.
Inform the others.
This is an M-Class planet
in orbit of a Type-G star.
We've located a continent
with edible vegetation
and an underground
water supply.
Unfortunately, the
region is subject
to windstorms.
Not exactly paradise.
You will adapt.
Practical
and to the point--
just like my wife.
She had a knack
for cutting to the truth.
She must have been
an efficient individual.
Ah, to say the least.
You would have enjoyed
her company.
You are not at all
like the Borg I knew.
As a drone,
I helped assimilate
many civilizations.
Now I have the opportunity
to help reconstruct one.
I find the experience...
gratifying.
So do I.
I'm curious--
has your crew ever considered
finding a planet of their own,
a place to settle down?
Captain Janeway
is committed
to getting Voyager
back to Earth.
That could take decades...
and there are
many dangers ahead.
We will adapt.
I suppose you will.
Neelix to Seven of Nine.
Yes?
Could I see you in Cargo Bay 2?
It's important.
Acknowledged.
I'm due for a final briefing
with your Mr. Tuvok.
I'll accompany you
to the Bridge.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but I've been doing
some research on our new allies,
and I have found something
very interesting.
In dozens of the ancient
folktales of my people,
there's a common theme.
They describe a phantom army
that appears out of thin air,
destroys entire colonies,
and vanishes in the blink
of an eye.
Sound familiar?
The subspace corridors.
Exactly!
Gedrin claims
they've been using them
as trade routes,
but I'm starting to wonder.
Your source material is
folktales, Mr. Neelix.
But many fables have
a basis in reality.
You've got
the collective knowledge
of thousands of species.
You could cross-reference
my findings.
It'll only take a few minutes.
( door chimes )
Come in.
You wanted to see me, Captain?
Yes.
I need a little history lesson.
Can't it... wait until after
we've reached the corridors?
I'm afraid not.
I've just had a conversation
with Mr. Neelix
and Seven of Nine.
They've been poring through
various databases
and have come up with
some surprising findings.
Surprising?
You told me the Vaadwaur
were a culture
of merchants
and scientists,
who expanded
their knowledge
by using subspace
corridors
to travel to
other worlds.
You were the envy of
hundreds of species,
some of whom eventually
wanted the corridors
for themselves.
Your point?
Let me give you another
version of events.
The Vaadwaur were
an aggressive culture,
who expanded
their territory
by using the corridors
to attack other worlds...
until some of those
worlds banded together
to defend themselves
and put an end to
the Vaadwaur threat
once and for all.
Would you care to set
the record straight?
That was 900 years ago.
If we're going to be
fighting side-by-side,
I have to trust you.
I need to be certain
you don't have any
ulterior motives.
Our only motive is survival.
If I were to take you
at your word,
the ancient Talaxians
might call me Vaadwaur--
"foolish."
That's what they
came to call anyone
who allowed themselves
to be deceived by an enemy.
There are hundreds of other
references just like it.
Both versions of our history
are true.
We did use the corridors
to explore,
and, on occasion,
expand our territory,
but, Captain, we have gone
from a population
of six billion to 600.
Our weapons are archaic.
Do you really think that
we are prepared to declare war
on the Delta Quadrant?
Not yet,
but right now,
it's  Voyager
I'm worried about.
The Turei are going
to be firing everything
they've got at my ship.
You might try
to take advantage of that.
What are you going to do--
put us all back into stasis?
We said we'd try to help you
make a new start,
and I want to keep that promise,
but I can't ignore history,
Mr. Gedrin.
Make yourself comfortable,
Chakotay...
( quietly ):
I don't know whether
to believe him or not.
What I wouldn't give
for a Betazoid about now.
If Mr. Neelix is right,
we should be ready
for anything.
Their technology
may be outdated,
but it can still do
a lot of damage.
Agreed.
Maintain a full
security alert
and have Tuvok keep
a weapons lock
on their primary
reactor.
Are we still proceeding
at 0600 hours?
Yes, but with a few
modifications.
What's Mr. Gaul's location?
He's in the
Central Chamber.
Hail him.
Captain, we've reactivated
73 assault vessels.
Our pilots are standing by.
I need to inform you
about a change of plan.
I want you to deactivate
the particle cannons
on all but ten of
your assault vessels.
Then we'll proceed
on schedule.
I don't understand.
Only ten of your ships
are going to engage the Turei.
The others will head directly
for the subspace corridors.
I see no reason
for those to be armed.
Something could go wrong.
Why leave them defenseless?
Voyager will
defend them.
What prompted this change?
You haven't been completely
honest about your past,
and that makes me a little
uncertain about the present.
Gedrin.
I suggest you listen to her.
Request denied, Captain.
It's not a request.
You can call it an ultimatum
if you like.
Unacceptable.
I'm going to leave this planet
in one hour with or without you.
We did not spend 900 years in
stasis to take orders from you.
Contact the battalion.
Tell them to prepare
for the attack.
I don't know about
the rest of you, but I'm
ready to get moving.
What's our status?
Impulse engines are on line.
Shields at maximum.
Weapons standing by.
Tom, prepare to initiate
the ascent sequence in...
CHAKOTAY:
Report.
Massive energy readings
coming from the Central Chamber.
It's the Vaadwaur.
They're launching
the first wave of ships.
17 vessels
have broken through
the surface.
They're at an altitude of
2,000 meters and
charging weapons.
Ma'am, they're not ascending
into orbit.
They're heading straight
for Voyager.
Tom?
Engaging thrusters.
Initiating ascent sequence.
Vaadwaur ships approaching
off our starboard bow.
Target phasers,
full spread.
( rumbling )
We're airborne.
What altitude do we need
on this planet, Tom,
before we can go to warp?
We'll have to clear
the thermosphere.
280 kilometers at least.
Shields at 92 percent.
Phasers.
We've disabled
four of their ships.
They've launched
another 39 vessels.
Evasive maneuvers.
It's no use.
They're closing
on all sides.
Direct hit to
the port thrusters.
We're losing altitude.
Reroute emergency power.
We need to get into orbit.
Targeting sensors off-line.
Switching to manual.
Harry, can you open
a secure channel
to the Turei ships
in orbit?
Yes, ma'am, but that
would give away our position.
They could lock on
with plasma charges.
I think it's time we reacquaint
a couple of old friends.
Hail them.
Voyager's shields
are weakening,
but they're gaining
altitude again.
They're approaching
the thermosphere.
Launch another squadron.
We've got nine more fighters
on our tail.
Aft shields down to 20 percent.
Captain, the Turei
are responding.
Put them through.
What do you want?
I've got a proposition
for you.
No more talk.
Prepare to be boarded.
Tell me, have you
been picking up weapons fire?
We have detected some unusual
energy signatures, yes.
That's because
we're under attack
by the Vaadwaur.
Impossible.
They were destroyed
centuries ago.
Some of us have survived.
JANEWAY:
They've got over 200 ships.
They said something
about wanting their
subspace corridors back.
I suggest we
join forces
and try to neutralize
the threat here and now.
What's more
important to you?
Deleting the records
of a Federation ship
that means you no harm,
or defending yourselves
against hundreds
of Vaadwaur fighters
who are determined to
invade your under-space?
I suggest you
pick your enemy.
Our sensors can't penetrate
the atmosphere.
How can we fight
an enemy we can't see?
We have access to one
of their surveillance
satellites.
We could use it
to transmit their vital
coordinates to you.
If this is a deception...
I'm having trouble establishing
a link with the satellite.
Our sensor array
took heavy damage.
I could access it
from the underground
control chamber.
Transport me there.
Not all of my people
are stuck in the past, Captain.
Tuvok, go with him.
MORIN:
We've impacted their hull.
There are breaches in
progress on two decks.
They'll have to reroute power
from their shields to seal them.
They'll have no choice
but to put down.
Have our ground
forces ready.
( grunts )
We've lost impulse
engines and navigation.
PARIS:
Thrusters are failing.
We're losing altitude.
Tuvok, status.
Tuvok?
KIM:
I've lost
his signal.
All hands, this is the Captain.
Initiate
emergency landing procedures
and arm yourselves.
If the Vaadwaur board this ship,
we'll fight them hand-to-hand
if we have to.
Once we've
secured  Voyager,
execute the crew.
Wait! We have hundreds
of bio-pods still intact.
Put them into stasis.
In a few hundred years,
maybe someone
will be kind enough
to revive them.
What is that?!
It's a plasma charge.
It came from orbit.
It's the Turei. They've
isolated our location.
How?!
One of the surveillance
satellites has been activated.
Shut it down!
They're blocking my commands.
I'm rotating
the carrier frequencies.
( gasps )
The chamber
is destabilizing.
We must evacuate.
No, not yet. If we're going
to succeed, I need to transmit
the signatures of our fighters
to the Turei.
You go.
Six Vaadwaur ships were just
destroyed by the Turei.
The others are breaking off
their attack.
Impulse engines?
Still off-line.
How about emergency power?
Barely enough for life-support.
Harry, the radiogenic particles
in the atmosphere--
could we use them
as a power source?
Well, we'd have to modify the
warp core's conversion matrix.
It could take hours.
What if we drew the particles
directly into
our plasma manifold?
That would give us
one hell of a boost.
It could also blow out
every power relay
on the ship.
Damned if we do;
damned if we don't.
Open the forward
nacelle ports
and reverse
the pressure gradient.
Take in 600 kilograms.
The chamber's collapsing, sir!
We'll take as many ships
as we can.
Try to reach the
subspace corridor!
( grunting )
( groans )
Particle concentration
at 3,000 parts per million.
Release the manifold.
Rerouting plasma to
the power conduits.
We have impulse.
Take us up.
KIM:
13 power relays just
blew out on Deck 6.
JANEWAY:
Steady.
PARIS:
We're crossing
the thermosphere.
JANEWAY:
Any sign of pursuit?
None. Looks like the Vaadwaur
have their hands full.
JANEWAY:
Altitude?
260 kilometers, 270...
( console beeps )
We've cleared
the thermosphere.
Go to warp, Mr. Paris.
Yes, ma'am.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 53167.9.
After two days,
there's been no sign
of the Vaadwaur
or the Turei.
However,
Seven of Nine has made
an unsettling discovery.
How many ships?
Astrometric scans detected
53 ion signatures
entering the corridors--
all Vaadwaur.
The underground chambers?
They were destroyed
by the Turei bombardment.
Captain...
I believe I made
an error in judgment.
Oh?
By awakening Gedrin,
I initiated
a chain of events
that nearly led
to our destruction.
I wanted to help revive
a civilization, not start a war.
You thought you were
acting out of compassion.
I might have done
the same thing,
but that doesn't
make it right, Seven.
The repercussions of this
could be catastrophic.
Their technology
is nine centuries out of date.
Their plans for conquest
are irrelevant.
They're a resourceful
species, determined.
They'll adapt.
I doubt we've seen
the last of them.