MAN:
Ares Four to Kumagawa.
How was the sunrise
from down there?
WOMAN:  Beautiful.
There was a little green
mixed in today.
It was really quite spectacular.
Sorry I missed it.
Next time, Lieutenant.
Any luck drilling
through that lava plain?
Roger that.
We broke through
the iron oxide barrier
and we're down to eight meters.
MAN:
We should have some samples
by the end of the day
if all goes well.
On to more important matters.
Received an uplink from Houston.
The Yankees won game five
of the World Series.
WOMAN:
You owe me 20 bucks.
It's not over yet.
There's still game six.
We're not the only ones
making history today.
Bokai just broke
DiMaggio's record.
MAN:
I don't believe it.
If you ask me, Houston's
been manipulating the stats.
WOMAN:
They do have a few too many
Kings fans at Mission Control.
Well, how else do you
explain Bokai beating out
the Yankee Clipper?
WOMAN:
Commander, we lost you
for a second there.
The ride got a little bumpy.
Stand by.
I'm picking up
some turbulence.
MAN:
At your altitude?
Checking Lidar.
What the hell...?
WOMAN:
John, what's going on?
There's an object
closing on my position--
azimuth 121.6.
Whatever it is, it's huge.
It's over
1,000 meters across.
MAN:
How could something that big
appear out of nowhere?
I don't know, but I'm
getting out of its way.
Firing thrusters.
WOMAN:
It's probably
just a solar flare.
Let's hope so.
It's no solar flare.
( light jazz playing )
( door chiming )
Come in.
( chiming )
Chakotay to the bridge.
MAN: This is
Transporter Room Two.
I'm trying to reach the bridge.
Your com signal
was routed here, sir.
Can you patch me through?
( warbled ):
Pardon me? Who is this?
Patch you through? Where?
Neelix?
Commander?
MAN: Double check on
the field generators.
( overlapping voices )
I see you're making some
changes to the computer core.
I've enhanced the
command sequencers
with Borg algorithms.
Well, your enhancements
are wreaking havoc
with our secondary systems.
Insignificant
malfunctions.
I will correct them.
I don't recall authorizing
any modifications.
The computer core
is inefficient.
It needed to be improved.
I appreciate your initiative,
but that's not up to you.
I've explained the value
of these enhancements
on several occasions,
but Lieutenant Torres
chose to ignore me.
I thought a demonstration
would be more persuasive.
Well, I doubt this one's
going to change her mind.
Clearly Voyager
is not yet ready
for assimilation.
A joke.
The doctor suggested
that I diffuse tense
situations with humor.
Good idea.
Now how about getting
these systems back up again
so I can get back
to my book?
We're experiencing
a ship-wide power drain.
This is unrelated
to my modifications.
KIM:
Senior officers to the bridge.
It's 2:00
in the morning, Ensign.
This better be more
than a little turbulence.
You won't be disappointed.
We've got level-nine
gravimetric distortions
closing on our position.
TUVOK:
They are emanating
from subspace.
On screen.
Shields.
It's heading
right toward us.
Evasive maneuvers.
Captain.
Say good morning
to 30 million terrajoules
of subspace energy.
This thing is following us.
I can't outrun it at impulse.
Go to warp.
It's disrupting our warp field.
If it any gets closer,
the gravimetric stresses
are going to rip
the plating off our hull.
Captain, I recognize
this phenomenon.
Its Borg designation
is Spatial Anomaly 521.
It's attracted to objects that
emit electromagnetic energy.
We have to cut power
and reverse our shield polarity.
Do it.
That was close.
I recognize
this anomaly, too.
It's called
a graviton ellipse.
According to
the Federation database,
it travels
through subspace
emerging occasionally
without warning.
Ellipses have only been
observed a handful of times.
Ares Four.
Commander?
One of the early
Mars missions.
The command module and
its pilot were engulfed
by a similar phenomenon
back in 2032.
I remember reading about that.
Two astronauts were stranded
on the surface for weeks
before a rescue ship arrived.
No one's gotten
this close to
a graviton ellipse
and lived to
tell about it.
This could be
a remarkable
opportunity.
Go to yellow alert.
Keep our power output
at minimum levels.
Match its course and speed,
but maintain a safe distance.
Aye, Captain.
I suggest we
launch a probe,
see if we can find
out what makes
this thing tick.
Make it fast.
There's no telling
when our visitor
is going to burrow back
into subspace.
I'm receiving telemetry
from the probe.
It appears to have
entered a stable core
within the anomaly
where gravimetric forces
are negligible.
The eye of the storm.
An apt metaphor.
Computer, run a
multispectral analysis
of the anomaly's core.
Analysis in progress.
The Borg developed shields
to get through
the gravimetric currents.
They intended to dissipate
the anomaly from within.
Perhaps we should
continue their efforts.
It would be shortsighted
to destroy it.
We should study
the phenomenon.
I didn't realize
you shared this crew's
penchant for exploration.
I am a Starfleet officer.
When the risks outweigh
the potential gain,
exploration
is illogical.
We can't predict what
we might find here, Seven.
One must allow
for the unexpected discovery.
Core analysis complete.
There are more than
2.8 billion compounds
in the core.
Fascinating.
The computer
has isolated
several synthetic
alloys native
to sector 0-0-1.
Titanium
and polymer composites.
These materials date back
to the 21st century.
They were used
in the construction
of Earth's
early spacecraft.
Commander Chakotay
mentioned a space
capsule
that was consumed
by a graviton ellipse.
These alloys are consistent
with the hull of that capsule.
An unexpected
discovery, indeed.
She was 46 meters,
92 metric tons,
powered by a third-generation
ion drive
and equipped
with a transpectral imager.
Ares Four was piloted
by Lieutenant John Kelly.
His ground team,
astronauts Rose Kumagawa
and Andrei Novakovich,
were close to completing
their survey mission
when Kelly reported an object
closing on his position.
Then he and the command module
disappeared off NASA's
Lidar scopes--
And into the
history books.
That incident
almost derailed
the Mars program.
TUVOK:
Mankind's first encounter
with a spatial anomaly.
Seven, you said
the Borg were working
on a way to get inside
a graviton ellipse.
Shield enhancements.
Well, maybe we could apply
the same enhancements
to the Flyer.
Captain, do you intend to try
to find the command module?
Or what's left of it.
By my calculations,
we have less than
16 hours
before the anomaly goes
back into subspace.
Then we have to work quickly.
Harry, B'Elanna,
help Seven modify
the Flyer's shields.
Tom, review the database
from the Ares Four mission.
It might tell us something
about this anomaly we've missed.
We're going to need
a mission leader.
I volunteer.
I thought you might.
Let's do it.
Something on your mind,
Seven?
The anomaly is as dangerous
and unpredictable now
as it was 300 years ago.
The Delta Flyer is
a little more advanced
than the Ares Four was.
We'll be taking
every precaution.
That may not be enough.
I appreciate your concern,
but this is my call.
Searching for
the command module seems
more sentimental
than scientific.
I can't argue with that.
If scientific knowledge
was all we were after,
then the Federation
would have built
a fleet of probes,
not starships.
Exploration is about seeing
things with your own eyes.
In this case,
we're exploring the past.
How will retrieving
this artifact
enhance your appreciation
of history?
By making us part of it,
in the same way
that excavating the obelisks
of ancient Vulcan
or finding
the Shroud of Kahless
made those explorers
part of their history.
( sighs ):
Here's the crux of it.
As a Borg, you didn't study
the past; you ingested it.
You never really developed
an appreciation for
humanity's history.
Maybe this is an opportunity
for you to do some
exploring of your own.
Are you ordering me
to join this mission?
Let's just say I'm encouraging
you to volunteer.
( sighs )
It's no solar flare.
Wow.
KUMAGAWA:
John, can you describe it?
It's... It's at least
1,000 meters wide. Bright.
NOVAKOVICH:
Your transmission
is breaking up.
It's generating
an electromagnetic radiation
interfering
with primary systems.
I can't get away from it.
Activating
the transpectral imager.
I'll record
as much data as I can.
It's right on top of me!
I'll transmit as much as I...
That's all she wrote.
NASA received Kelly's
last telemetry
at 0922 hours,
October 19, 2032.
I thought I was
the Mars buff.
You seem to know more about
the Ares Four than I do.
The Mars missions paved the way
for the exploration of space.
Kelly was one of
my childhood heroes.
Yeah, mine, too.
That's dedication.
The man's life's
about to end,
but he won't stop
taking readings.
Makes you wonder
if those old-timers
were made of sterner
stuff than we are.
You think we have it easy?
Are you kidding?
Warp drive, shields,
transporters--
We're traveling
in the lap of luxury.
Kelly and Kumagawa,
Armstrong and Glenn,
they were the real pioneers.
Am I interrupting?
We're just admiring someone,
a fellow explorer.
Hero worship--
the glorification
of an individual's
accomplishments.
I guess you didn't have
many role models growing up.
In the collective,
personal accomplishments
are irrelevant.
The shield modifications
to the Delta Flyer are
complete.
We're ready
for launch.
We?
You'll need
someone familiar
with Borg technology
to monitor the shields.
I'm volunteering.
Well, you don't sound
too happy about it.
I'm not,
but this mission
can benefit
from my expertise.
In that case...
welcome aboard.
I'm preparing an inoculant
to counter the effects
of gravimetric radiation.
Of course,
if you were a hologram,
you'd simply adjust
your mobile emitter.
That's what I did
on Arakis Prime,
one of my first
away missions.
I don't recall that.
This was before
you came aboard.
Such an
enchanting planet--
crystalline glaciers...
magnesium vapor
atmosphere.
I had to stop my
metallurgical scans
just to admire the
sheer beauty of it--
to... "smell the roses,"
to coin a phrase.
An inefficient use
of your time.
Perhaps.
We're all finished here,
except for one thing.
Would you mind
recording some images
when you're
inside the ellipse
for those of us not lucky
enough to make the trip?
You envy my participation
on this mission.
There isn't a crewman
aboard who doesn't.
Why?
I can only tell you
how I felt that morning
when I materialized
on Arakis Prime.
I left my footprints
in the magnesite dust
and thought, "one small
step for a hologram,
one giant leap
for mankind."
To coin a phrase.
Well, I know the sentiment
isn't exactly original,
but the fact is
I was exhilarated.
Chakotay to Seven of Nine.
Report to Shuttle Bay Two.
Good luck.
We're approaching
the perimeter in five, four...
three, two, one.
We're within
2,000 kilometers.
Gravimetric interference
is increasing.
It's nothing compared
to what they're going through.
They're really getting
knocked around in there.
The shields have weakened,
but they're still holding.
Harry, keep your finger
on that tractor beam
in case we have
to pull them out.
They're approaching
the anomaly's core.
We've lost
sensor contact.
Harry.
The com link is still active.
The gravimetric shear
is increasing.
I'm reading diminished
turbulence directly ahead.
Full thrusters, Tom.
Punch us through.
Chakotay to Voyager.
We're in.
CHAKOTAY:
I wish you could
see this, Captain.
It's incredible.
We're all ears.
It's very calm,
no gravimetric distortions.
The E.M. activity is creating
a natural luminescence.
Tom called it "mood lighting."
PARIS:
Hey, B'Elanna, it's
the perfect romantic getaway.
I'll take your word
for it.
CHAKOTAY:
We've detected asteroid
fragments, pieces of vessels,
matter from every quadrant
of the galaxy.
Next time I lose something,
I'll know where to look.
Instead of a graviton ellipse
we should call it the
"kitchen sink anomaly."
The chemical interactions
have even created
a primitive atmosphere.
PARIS:
Nothing you'd want
to breathe, of course.
What do you
make of it, Seven?
SEVEN:
Well, I suppose
it's intriguing.
Some of the matter appears to be
extra-dimensional in origin.
Sounds like
this anomaly's
gotten around.
Any sign of the Ares
command module?
PARIS:
We're picking up traces
of the hull,
but our sensor readings
are being refracted
by all the debris in here.
That was a gravimetric surge
caused by the anomaly
altering its course
by .006 degrees.
We just had a big jolt
out here.
CHAKOTAY:
We didn't feel a thing.
By our estimate, you have
five hours, 36 minutes
before the anomaly
returns to subspace.
You better get a move on.
CHAKOTAY:
Understood.
I'm having difficulty
isolating the debris
from the command module.
I'll lay in a search pattern.
It may take a couple of hours
to cover an area this large.
Seven and I can use the time
to take some samples.
We'll get a better idea
of where this anomaly's been.
We should focus on achieving
our objective and returning
to Voyager.
We're not here
just to find the module.
We've got
an opportunity to...
To explore.
I am familiar
with our mission.
In that case,
let's get started.
The fossilized
microbes in this ore
appear to have had
metallic membranes.
We've speculated
about the possibility
of metallic life-forms,
but we've never
discovered one.
You're excited
by this discovery.
This piece of rock
is billions of years
older than Earth,
from a time when the
galaxy was still forming.
Here.
Commander.
Take it.
You're holding
a piece of history.
Maybe even the beginnings
of life itself.
Unlikely.
It's more likely
than you think.
This anomaly is
as old as anything
we've ever encountered.
I could spend a lifetime
studying the things
it's collected.
And leave Voyager
without a first officer.
They'd manage.
Paleontology was
always my first love.
It's the reason
I joined Starfleet.
Why didn't you pursue it?
My sense of responsibility
got in the way--
First the Maquis,
then Voyager.
What I wanted
always seemed
to take a backseat.
Do you remember
what you wanted to be
before you were
assimilated?
I was assimilated
when I was a child.
I knew I wanted
to be a paleontologist
when I was six.
A ballerina.
Maybe it's not too late.
It was a juvenile fantasy.
Those are the ones
that stick with you.
PARIS:
Heads up, folks.
I think we're getting close.
I've isolated the module.
Bearing 39, mark 1-5.
There.
It appears to be intact.
I'm reading hull
breaches and corrosion
but, all things considered,
it's pretty well preserved.
We weren't expecting to find
a fragment this big.
We can't just stow it
in the aft section.
We'll use a tractor beam
to tow it back
to Voyager.
Captain, the
anomaly just made
another course change--
.003 degrees.
That's the third one in an hour.
Something has to be
attracting it.
There's nothing
on the sensors.
I think it enjoys
being unpredictable.
We know it has a taste
for electromagnetic energy.
So what could generate
an E.M. field large enough
to get its attention
but still not show up
on sensors?
An energy burst
from a pulsar,
a neutrino cloud.
Dark matter.
Realign the sensor array
to scan for E.M. fluctuations.
I've got
a spatial disturbance...
three million kilometers away.
It's a dark matter asteroid.
Bingo.
The anomaly's heading
right for it.
Time to impact?
Four minutes. Captain,
we can't predict how the impact
will affect the anomaly.
But it's a safe bet
it won't be a gentle nudge.
Janeway to Delta Flyer.
We've got a problem.
The anomaly's
on a collision course
with a dark-matter asteroid.
We've located
the Mars orbiter.
We're adapting
a tractor beam;
give us a minute.
You don't have it;
get out of there.
Captain...
Now.
Is the tractor beam ready?
Just about, sir.
Lock onto the module
and take us out.
We don't have time.
I gave you an order.
Commander.
We're not leaving
without that module.
Tom!
Captain, both the anomaly
and the asteroid
are accelerating.
They're attracting
each other like
a pair of magnets.
At this rate,
it'll impact in...
56 seconds.
Chakotay, you've got
less than a minute.
Acknowledged.
The module is slowing us down.
Maintain tractor lock.
How long until we clear
the anomaly?
At our current speed,
40 seconds.
We can do it.
30 seconds to impact.
They're still not clear.
Chakotay, status.
We're on our way.
20 seconds.
The gravimetric distortions
are increasing.
The Flyer.
I've lost the signal.
How badly is he damaged?
He's got a severe concussion
and internal injuries.
We need to get him
back to Voyager.
That may not be possible.
Communications,
shields and propulsion
are still off-line.
Well, he's
stable for now.
I'll give you a hand.
We can repair the shields,
but the engines
are unsalvageable.
It can't be that bad.
It's worse.
The anomaly is showing signs
of returning to subspace.
We have less than two hours.
( groaning )
He's regaining
consciousness.
Easy.
Easy. Lie still.
It feels like I went ten rounds
with an Andorian.
More like 20.
You were hit with
a plasma discharge.
The gravimetric surge
from the asteroid
caught us at the edge
of the anomaly,
tossed us back inside.
The command module?
It's adrift, 300 meters
off our port bow.
Then we can still
salvage it.
Not so fast.
We can't get engines
or shields back on-line,
not to mention
a tractor beam.
We'll be lucky to
get out of this
in one piece.
I can help.
You're in worse shape
than this ship.
You want to help?
Lie in the bed--
doctor's orders.
Another
gravimetric surge.
I'll see if I can reinforce
the structural integrity field.
You might try drawing power
from auxiliary life support.
The system was
damaged as well.
What about
the secondary relays?
They're off-line.
That doesn't give us
many choices.
Try rerouting
the phaser couplings.
We explored that option
while you were unconscious.
Then maybe you can
bring me up-to-date.
There's no time.
I suggest you recuperate.
We have the situation
under control.
It doesn't look that way
from here.
I'm still in command
of this mission. I want
to know what's going on.
Very well.
We were ordered by the Captain
to leave this anomaly,
but you chose
to disobey that command.
As a result of your obsession
with the module,
we are now trapped
along with it.
In all probability,
we won't survive without...
Point taken.
Now, why don't you continue...
without the attitude?
An inventory of
the damaged systems.
Read it for yourself.
I made a mistake.
I put the mission
at risk.
You put our lives at risk.
Well, if we don't make it out...
someone's bound
to come looking for us
in a few hundred years.
Diffusing a tense situation
with humor... remember?
JANEWAY:
Voyager to Delta Flyer.
They're using a probe
as a transmission relay.
Voyager to Chakotay,
please respond.
We can't detect you.
Captain, we can hear you.
I'm matching their frequency.
Voyager, this is the Delta
Flyer, respond.
JANEWAY:
Are you all right?
What's your status?
We've sustained heavy damage,
Captain, but we're alive.
It's good to hear your voice.
We could install
the same shielding
on a class-two shuttle,
and take it in.
It took us hours to
make the modifications
to the Flyer.
We've only got 82 minutes
before this thing
disappears into subspace.
It may be possible
to modify a tractor beam
to cut through
the gravimetric interference.
You'll never be able to get it
all the way to the core.
Start working on it anyway.
You said all the energy
conduits are fused?
Correct. We can't get power
to any of the primary systems.
If the replicators were working,
we could whip up a new
plasma manifold
and be on our way.
What if I could get you
an old manifold?
Excuse me?
The command module
may be three centuries old,
but the power
distribution system
isn't that different
from the Flyer's.
Right here.
This control panel
in the main cockpit--
It was called
an ion distributor.
With a few tweaks,
it could be modified
to channel warp plasma.
SEVEN:
Even if it were possible,
we'd have to obtain
the object before we
can adapt it.
Do you have
enough power to beam
one of you to the module?
Yes, ma'am. I'll go.
Not so fast, Tom.
If another
gravimetric surge hits,
we'll need you at the helm.
Seven?
Are you encouraging me
to volunteer again, Captain?
You read my mind.
Come on.
Just a little closer.
That's it for thrusters,
but I got us within
transporter range.
Ready?
Stand by.
Ironic. You're doing
what I've always dreamt of.
Remember,
when you set foot
in that module,
you'll be stepping
into history.
History is irrelevant.
Irrelevant?
Do me a favor.
When you're over there,
download whatever you can
from their database,
and also, take a minute
to look around...
so you can tell us
what it was like.
There may not be time...
but I'll try.
Good luck.
PARIS:
What's it like in there?
Dark.
The ambient temperature
is minus 260 degrees.
There appear to be fractures
in the aft bulkhead.
Is the cockpit intact?
Yes.
I've brought the main
computer on-line.
KELLY:
I've lost contact with
the team on the surface...
and I can't get a fix
on my position.
PARIS:
What was that?
There's an active data file.
It appears to contain
log entries.
Can you play them for us?
I believe so.
( grunting )
Consider it my last request.
KELLY:
...and I can't get
a fix on my position,
but I'm alive, and the C.M.
seems to be intact.
( sighing ):
I'm inside this...
whatever it is.
Could you hear that, Chakotay?
It's amazing.
Everyone assumed
he was killed instantly.
It's very calm--
like I'm in the
eye of a hurricane...
something spooky.
The way I figure it,
if there's a way in,
there's got to be a way out.
I'm going to fire up
the transpectral imager
before I initiate another
engine burn...
collect as much data as I can.
Jeannie, I may not be bringing
you back a Mars rock,
but I promise you, I'm going to
do everything I can to get home.
Ares Four, mission record,
October 23:
I'm starting to feel like Jonah.
How long was he in the belly
of that whale? Three days?
I got him beat
by a day or two already.
The E.M. interference
is disrupting communications
and Lidar,
and I can't see the stars,
so there's no way
I can get a fix on my position.
If this thing's moving as fast
as it was when it pulled me in,
I could be a long way
from Mars by now.
The imager's
been working overtime,
cataloguing
all the matter in here,
but a lot of it defies analysis.
I think we're going to need to
make room on the periodic table.
Where the hell am I?
Power levels have dropped
another 15%
since my last systems check.
( metallic scraping )
I... I think I just saw
another spacecraft.
Either that...
or all this dehydrated food
has gone to my head.
( beeping )
I got it. The hull's made
of some kind of alloy.
I can't make
heads or tails of it.
I shouldn't have been
so dismissive.
I remember
giving Kumagawa a hard time
when she claimed
she saw a UFO over the Gulf.
I told her it was a meteor
or another piece of Mir.
I guess I owe you
an apology, Rose.
Ares Four, mission record,
October 25.
This has been
a nice place to visit,
but I'm ready to come home.
I've prepped the ion drive,
channeled all the power
from the thruster reserves
into the main tank.
I have enough fuel
for one last engine burn.
Wish me luck.
Ignition sequence.
( power surging )
Five, four,
three, two...
( engines roaring )
I'm losing pitch control.
Gyros aren't responding.
( engines powering down )
Power failure.
I've got to abort.
I'm not going to make it!
KELLY:
All systems go.
Watch me, Dad.
I'm flying.
Bad landing.
Call the medevac team.
( monitor fritzing )
Paris to Seven. Status?
I've located the device,
but it's fused to the hull.
Stand by.
Make it quick.
We've got less than
15 minutes.
Understood.
KELLY:
All systems go.
Watch me, Dad. I'm flying.
( imitates crash landing )
Bad landing.
Call the medevac team.
( laughing )
John Kelly's first flight...
not exactly a-okay.
Remember that, Dad?
I jumped off the roof
with a parachute
made out of blankets.
I guess I didn't calculate
the aerodynamics.
Of course...
I was only six.
I guess this is
John Kelly's last flight.
This time...
I can't blame it on pilot error.
This time... no regrets.
What I've seen... proves...
We were right to come out here.
We're not alone.
I know that now.
The module's losing power.
I'm taking life support
off-line.
Rerouting whatever's left
to the imager.
Keep it running...
as long as possible.
Mission Control...
Dad...
Whoever finds this...
do me a favor.
Take all the data
I've collected...
and put it to good use.
I hope you don't look at this
as a failure.
( coughing )
I don't.
Actually...
I do have one regret.
I never found out--
who won the World Series.
( sighing )
I'm tired.
I can't...
Paris to Seven.
How's it going over there?
I have the distributor.
I'm downloading Lieutenant
Kelly's database.
Hurry. We're running
out of time.
( beeping )
Lock onto my bio-signature
and my com badge.
PARIS: Seven?
Energize.
Delta Flyer, report.
PARIS:  We're trying
to integrate the distributor.
Stand by, Captain.
How long do they have?
Four minutes.
Try bypassing
the power couplings.
No effect.
Resequence the ion modulators;
see if that does it.
SEVEN:
Power conversion in progress.
We have propulsion,
shields.
The plasma flow
is still fluctuating.
Stay on top of it.
Paris to Voyager.
JANEWAY: Go ahead.
Open the shuttle bay doors;
we're coming home.
Acknowledged.
Laying in an escape trajectory.
The ellipse
is returning to subspace.
The Flyer.
They're approaching
the perimeter...
2,000 meters... 1,800.
The anomaly's submerging.
Are we in tractor range?
TUVOK: Not yet.
Take us closer.
Captain?
Do it.
They are still
out of reach.
Another 300 meters.
Closer.
We'll be pulled
right in with them.
Just a few more meters.
We're too close!
I've got a lock.
Reverse thrusters,
full impulse.
Captain's log,
Stardate 53301.2:
the away team collected
over 60 terraquads of data
on the anomaly.
Before we begin
to analyze them,
we've decided
to pay our respects
to an old colleague.
Space.
Literally,
it means "nothing..."
a vacuum
between stars and planets,
but by the same token,
it means everything.
It's what connects
all our worlds--
Vulcan, Kronos,
Talax, Earth.
Centuries ago,
mankind sent its first wave
of explorers into that void.
Astronauts like Mr. Kelly.
They paved the way
for the first colonies,
the first starships,
for those of us
who've made space our home.
We commend
the spirit and the bravery
of Lieutenant John Mark Kelly
as we commit his body...
to space.
He will not be forgotten.
Captain...
I did not know
this individual.
Had I encountered him
while I was a Borg,
I would have found
his technology
unworthy of assimilation.
But we are more alike
than one might think.
In a sense,
his desire to explore
was not unlike
a quest for perfection.
His contribution
helped secure humanity's future
and in some ways, my own.
( softly ):
The Yankees...
in six games.
All hands, attention.
Honor guard.
( whistle blowing )