Naomi Wildman, state
your purpose here.
I was waiting for you.
Kadis-Kot, remember?
Our weekly game?
Reschedule for tomorrow.
I'm working now.
Redecorating isn't work.
Aesthetics are irrelevant.
I'm modifying the alcove
to function as a cortical
processing subunit.
That was my next guess.
Then I won't need to
explain its purpose.
Okay, you win.
What do you do with
the cortical processing, uh...
Subunit.
On Borg vessels, there's
one in each unimatrix.
It downloads
newly assimilated
data to the drones.
But Voyager
isn't a Borg vessel,
and you're not
a drone anymore.
Voyager collects
a great deal of information--
sensor scans,
navigational projections,
engineering updates,
away team reports,
scientific analyses.
The results of our
Kadis-Kot tournament?
That, too.
The crew must read and study
this information--
an inefficient procedure.
These data nodes are downloading
the information into the alcove.
Which is going to download it
into you.
Precisely.
In a matter of hours,
I will assimilate
several months worth of data.
Can I try it sometime?
Your physiology is...
different from mine.
Guess I'll stick
to reading my lessons
and listening
to Neelix tell stories.
I will see you tomorrow.
Can I watch?
Okay, tomorrow.
COMPUTER:
Warning. Plate is hot.
Now you tell me.
You go for authenticity
and what do you get?
Second-degree burns.
I've been slaving
over that replicator
program for hours.
What was this bizarre
rumor I heard
about half the crew on
Deck 5 getting pregnant?
Oh, that.
The Doctor was running
generational projections
on the Sick Bay computer.
Tom Paris happened
to glance at the monitor
and jumped to conclusions.
Wasn't long before
Neelix was asking me
if he could turn Cargo Bay 1
into a nursery.
Word travels fast
on this ship, hmm?
Warp 10.
Oh, by the way,
I meant to tell you...
there's a class-K nebula
25 light-years off starboard.
We should take a look.
A major detour
for a minor nebula.
We are explorers,
remember?
Permission granted.
( replicator beeps )
Main course,
a recipe I've never tried.
But we are explorers,
remember?
COMPUTER:
Regeneration cycle complete.
Seven of Nine
to Lieutenant Torres.
Lieutenant Torres, respond.
TORRES: Good morning, Seven.
This better be important.
I must speak with you at once.
I'm picking up some interesting
graviton fluctuations
about ten
light-years away.
Can you be
more specific?
Not at this
distance. Tom...
alter course.
I want to take
a closer look.
Chakotay had his heart set
on that nebula we're headed for.
He'll have to wait.
Captain, I need permission
to shut down the sensor grid.
Seven thinks a couple of insects
are disrupting the power flow.
A mating pair
of photonic fleas,
to be more accurate,
and possibly their offspring.
And how did you arrive
at this theory?
Last night,
I downloaded six months
of ship status reports
into my new cortical subunit
while I was regenerating.
PARIS:
Learn while you sleep.
I tried that once--
gave me a headache.
Go on.
Eight weeks ago,
an away team encountered
a Kartelan freighter carrying
supplies from Sector 492,
a territory that included
a former Talaxian colony.
Mr. Neelix used
the opportunity to acquire
12 kilograms of amber spice--
a delicacy among his people.
What does that have to do
with the sensor grid?
On the same day,
Ensign Kim was
repairing a replicator
in the Mess Hall.
I remember that--
Neelix told me
to stick around
to try something he was cooking.
No doubt made
with the amber spice,
which contained the larvae
of the photonic fleas.
How could you possibly
know that?
Because I also downloaded data
regarding their life cycles.
The larvae flew out
of the spice jar
in search of their
primary source of
nourishment--
plasma particles.
The conduits within
the nearby sensor grid
contain an unlimited supply
of these particles.
Ensign Kim had unwittingly
given the creatures access
by exposing the grid.
The now-mature creatures
periodically
tap into the conduit
for nourishment.
When they do,
the sensor emitters
momentarily
lose their resolution.
A logical, though
highly speculative, analysis.
Let's find a more
suitable home for them.
I'm picking
up graviton
fluctuations.
Take us out of warp.
On screen.
Anybody want to hazard a guess?
They are hailing us.
On screen.
I recommend maximum shielding.
There are a few technical issues
I haven't worked out yet.
There's a massive graviton surge
coming from that thing.
Shields to full.
Your apparatus appears
to be destabilizing.
If I don't find a way to repair
this power core, they'll be able
to see the explosion
all the way to, uh...
Where did you say you were from?
I didn't...
but we're from
a planet called Earth.
All the way to... Earth.
Can we ask you
what it's supposed to do?
Catapult a vessel across space
in the time it takes to say,
"catapult a vessel
across space."
It'll make warp drive
look like a wooden sled.
Maybe we can help you
with that power core.
Hmm?
The core sends a graviton surge
through the projectors
which locks onto a ship
and sends it hurtling
into null space
to emerge a few hours later,
hundreds, if not thousands
of light-years away.
I'm curious
why you built this catapult.
Simple-- I've been looking
for a way to get home.
We know the feeling.
I'd been exploring
an unstable wormhole.
Before I knew it, I was here
and my home planet was there.
I was facing a journey
of at least ten years.
Instead, I decided
to build a catapult.
Have you tested it yet?
Two weeks ago, I sent a probe
nearly 600 light-years,
but it destabilized
the core.
I've been trying to
fix it ever since.
We can send an engineering team
over to help you.
No, no, it's too dangerous.
I wouldn't send my own crew
in there.
Then we could find
a way to adjust the
core reaction from here.
A few well-timed
graviton pulses
from our deflector dish
might do it.
That's generous,
but I have nothing
to give in return.
We're not asking
for anything in return.
You could use the catapult
after I've made my jump.
It should still
be functional.
A thousand light-years
won't exactly get
you back to Earth...
But it would cut a few
years off our trip.
If you're successful,
and if I'm satisfied
a jump would be safe
for Voyager,
then we'll take you up
on that offer. Thank you.
Let's get started.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Good morning.
Perhaps not.
The alien, Mr. Tash,
is trying to deceive us.
His catapult is the same type
of technology
that was used
to trap Voyager
in the Delta Quadrant
five years ago.
I scanned the
catapult myself.
Sensors didn't pick up
anything unusual.
You spent the night
in your new alcove.
Processing the same information
and cross-referencing it
with Voyager's database.
When the catapult
destabilized yesterday,
astrometric sensors recorded
a momentary burst
of epsilon radiation.
Unusual, but not unheard of.
Epsilon radiation is
one the byproducts
of a tetryon reactor.
According to your own entries
in the database,
your only encounter
with that kind of technology
occurred five years ago
in the Alpha Quadrant.
A coherent tetryon beam
locked onto Voyager,
and you were hit
by a massive
displacement wave,
which pulled you across
70,000 light-years
in a matter of minutes.
The source of
that tetryon beam
was the Caretaker's Array.
Mr. Tash claims that his
catapult will be able to do
something very similar.
He didn't want us
to send over a repair team.
Out of concern
for our safety.
It's obvious
he was trying to hide
his tetryon reactor.
The first time we met
a Caretaker, we were pulled
halfway across the galaxy.
The second time
we were almost killed.
I'm not eager
for a third round.
Is this any way
to treat a colleague?
Not so much as a molecule
of Caretaker DNA.
Thank you, Doctor.
There's a tetryon reactor
powering your catapult.
You didn't want us
to find it, did you?
Unless you answer my questions,
I'll resume course,
and you can ask
somebody else for help.
Look, I acquired the tetryon
reactor at great cost.
This territory is
full of species
who would do anything for
such advanced technology,
including steal it.
I apologize for
the deception,
but you do understand.
We made an agreement
to cooperate.
I see no reason
not to continue.
Thank you, Captain.
Keep me informed
on your progress.
That reactor had
to come from somewhere.
I can't just ignore
the possibility of
a Caretaker nearby.
Keep scanning.
See what you can find.
There is another
possibility.
The reactor may have come
from the same Array
that brought Voyager
to the Delta Quadrant.
That's a long shot, Seven.
Maybe not.
Again, according
to your own reports,
you believed the only way
to keep the Array from
falling into the wrong hands
was to destroy it.
It's possible
the destruction
was incomplete.
And one of the reactors
survived?
We scanned for debris.
There was nothing left but some
fused pieces of metal alloy.
I wish to reexamine the sensor
records from that event.
In case we were mistaken.
Yes.
Go right ahead.
Computer,
describe the debris remaining
after the Array was destroyed.
Particulate dust
and metallic fragments
composed of an unknown alloy,
vapor composed of hydrogen,
helium, mercury and argon.
Was there anything left
of the tetryon reactor?
Negative.
Specify the yield
of the tricobalt device.
20,000 teracochranes.
Who programmed the device?
Commander Tuvok.
Display the detonation.
Advance the image
by .01 seconds.
Again.
Isolate grid 3-7 and magnify.
Is that a tractor beam?
Insufficient sensor data.
Identify its source.
Identify the isolated section
of the Array.
Secondary power core.
Which contained
a tetryon reactor.
Affirmative.
Commander, I've been
reviewing the data
on the destruction
of the Caretaker's Array.
Unfortunately, the sensor
records are incomplete.
I don't doubt it.
We were being attacked
by the Kazon.
Half the ship's
systems were down.
A single Kazon vessel.
Armed to the teeth.
Commander, you fired
the tricobalt charge
that destroyed the Array.
Correct.
Under the Captain's orders?
Did you also program
the charge?
Yes.
Under the Captain's orders
as well?
Not directly.
I determined the yield.
20,000 teracochranes.
That's correct.
According to sensor estimates
of the Array's hull integrity,
a charge of half that yield
would have been
sufficient.
The Captain wanted nothing left
for the Kazon to use.
I calculated a yield
certain to produce that result.
Something may have
escaped the blast--
one of the tetryon reactors.
But we scanned for debris.
The charge you detonated
tore an opening in subspace.
And that's where
the reactor went?
Yes.
How?
It was pushed there
by a tractor beam.
Do you have evidence
of a tractor beam?
Perhaps.
Speculation is not evidence.
There was no tractor beam,
because there was no ship
in the vicinity to generate one,
unless you can prove otherwise.
Thank you, Commander.
Looking for a midnight snack?
I require information.
I'm attempting to determine
whether the
catapult technology
was derived from
the Caretaker's Array.
So I heard.
A fascinating theory.
It's got my mind spinning.
How long were you
in the vicinity of the Array
before Voyager arrived?
About a year.
Kes was on a nearby planet
and, uh, we were
getting very close.
Did you ever encounter
the Caretaker directly?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
In my opinion, any being
powerful enough to grab ships
from the other side
of the galaxy should be avoided.
According to
Voyager's database,
he claimed
he was searching
for a genetically
compatible mate.
Did you believe
that explanation?
I had no reason to doubt it,
though it did seem
a bit excessive.
I mean, all those ships.
What happened to them?
Well, after he sampled
the crew's DNA,
he sent them back where
they came from, I suppose.
You know, Kes always thought
something more was going on,
but she had
quite an imagination.
Were there any
other ships in the area
after Voyager arrived?
Only the Kazon.
But the Caretaker
could have pulled in
another vessel...
a cloaked ship,
perhaps.
Seven, what are you getting at?
A third ship hidden
from both Voyager
and the Kazon.
What was it doing there?
Preventing the tetryon reactor
from being destroyed.
Kes was right.
Something was going on.
Voyager's sensor logs were
damaged in the Kazon attack.
I can't be certain.
Maybe I can help.
The sensor records
off my ship
weren't damaged.
I can give them to you.
The tetryon reaction is stable.
Graviton field is set
for a 100 light-year jump.
The catapult's locking on
to him.
We're being hailed.
On screen.
I'll contact you the moment
I reenter normal space.
Thank you, Captain.
My pleasure.
Catapult is at full power.
Good-bye to you all.
Final launch sequence
has been initiated.
He's gone.
How long before we can
expect to hear from him?
If his vessel survived,
one or two hours.
Seven of Nine
to Commander Chakotay.
Go ahead.
I require your assistance
in the Astrometrics Lab.
On my way.
Computer,
seal the doors.
Deactivate all sensors
within this room.
Acknowledged.
What's this about?
I believe
Voyager's presence
in the Delta Quadrant
is no accident.
You and the crew
have been stranded here
intentionally.
By whom?
Captain Janeway.
The Captain and Tuvok
were involved in
a Federation conspiracy.
They're in collusion
with the Caretaker
and possibly
the Cardassians.
I see.
And the point
of this conspiracy?
I believe
they're attempting to establish
a military presence
in the Delta Quadrant.
That's quite a theory.
Perhaps you haven't heard
of the Jankata Accord.
"No species shall
enter another Quadrant
for the purpose
of territorial expansion."
The Federation signed it,
the Cardassians signed it,
and Captain Janeway would be
the last person to violate it.
Improbable as it may sound,
I've found compelling evidence
to support my theory.
What kind of evidence?
I've analyzed over 30 million
teraquads of data
regarding Voyager's
activities over
the past five years.
It's quite clear
that we've been the victim
of an elaborate deception.
I don't have the benefit
of a cortical processor.
Why don't you give me
the abridged version?
In the months before Voyager's
arrival,
Neelix recorded
the appearance of 52 vessels,
including this one.
CHAKOTAY:
A Cardassian warship.
A remarkable
coincidence.
Only days before
Voyager's arrival,
the Cardassians were already
in the Delta Quadrant.
The Caretaker was trying
to find a mate, remember?
He was pulling ships
from all over the galaxy.
I'm familiar
with the Caretaker's actions.
In each instance,
he would examine the crew's DNA
and when he failed
to find a genetic match,
he would release the vessel,
but in this instance,
Neelix's sensors indicated
the ship vanished.
Obviously, it was returned
to the Alpha Quadrant. Why?
You seem to have
all the answers.
I believe the Cardassians
were sent back
to deliver strategic information
regarding the Delta Quadrant.
Conjecture.
Extrapolation.
I can believe the Cardassians
might be involved in this,
but not Starfleet.
There are precedents
for unauthorized missions
of this type, Commander.
According
to the Federation database,
the Maquis were victims
of several of them.
All right,
you've got my attention.
You said that Tuvok and
Captain Janeway were involved.
Tell me how.
At the same time
the Cardassians were meeting
with the Caretaker,
your Maquis vessel
was infiltrated
with a Starfleet agent.
Tuvok.
Your navigator.
He guided your ship
to prearranged coordinates
in the Badlands,
where the Caretaker
locked onto you.
Once you were pulled
into the Delta Quadrant,
Tuvok could've
secretly transmitted
final instructions
to the Caretaker.
A short time later,
Captain Janeway
guided Voyager
to the same coordinates
and was also pulled
into the Delta Quadrant.
All of these events took place
within a matter of days.
I find that suspicious.
I'll admit, the timing seems
a little convenient,
but that doesn't mean
there was a master plan.
Why did the Captain
destroy the Array?
So the Kazon couldn't use it
to attack the Ocampa.
That's what she told the crew,
but I believe she intended
to remain
in the Delta Quadrant all along.
If the Array
had remained intact,
you and all the others
would have insisted on using it
to return home.
She was keeping it
from the Kazon.
The Captain ordered
Commander Tuvok
to destroy the Array.
He fired
two tricobalt devices.
Are those weapons
normally carried
on Federation starships?
No.
Yet they were part
of Voyager's arsenal.
Why?
I can't explain that.
I can.
Neither phasers nor torpedoes
are capable
of creating a tear in subspace.
A tricobalt device is.
As Tuvok detonated the device,
a cloaked ship locked on
to one of the Array's
tetryon reactors
and pushed it
through the tear
into subspace,
protecting it
from the blast,
and hiding it from Voyager's
sensors...
but the Captain
and Tuvok knew exactly
where it was going.
Once Voyager left
the area, the reactor
was retrieved
and began a similar journey
carried by a series of vessels,
until it was finally
delivered to Mr. Tash.
Who used it
to build the catapult.
He was waiting here
for Voyager
and for the final phase
of the mission.
Which is what, exactly?
I don't think
Captain Janeway is planning
to use the catapult to get
Voyager closer to home.
I think she's going to use it
to bring in more vessels
from the Alpha Quadrant.
If I'm correct,
this region of space
will soon be occupied
by a Federation-Cardassian
invasion force.
You've uncovered
some interesting facts,
but your interpretation
is farfetched.
These are random incidents.
Granted, some of them
are hard to explain,
but there's
no conspiracy here.
Stardate 51008.
Captain Janeway allows Kes
to leave Voyager.
Neelix told me
that Kes had suspicions
about the Caretaker.
Was the Captain trying
to silence her?
Stardate 51462.
The Doctor's program
is transmitted to
a Starfleet vessel
on the outskirts
of the Alpha Quadrant--
an attempt by the Captain
to contact Earth,
or a secret communiqué
informing Starfleet
of her progress?
Stardate 50984.
Janeway forges an alliance
with the Borg.
Stardate 51762.
A cease-fire with the Hirogen.
Stardate 52861.
A non-aggression pact
with the Terkellian.
She called each incident,
"diplomacy."
I believe she was trying
to establish a tactical
infrastructure
in the Delta Quadrant.
Over the past five years,
Captain Janeway
has altered course 263 times
in the name of exploration.
In reality,
she was mapping the region
and collecting
strategic data regarding...
I get the point.
You still doubt my suspicions,
but can you be certain
I'm wrong?
Absolutely certain?
No.
Until you are,
you mustn't allow
Captain Janeway
to retain control
of the catapult.
I'm picking up a transmission,
heavily distorted.
He made it.
Can you clear it up?
TASH:
Success, Captain--
5,000 light-years.
Are you all right?
A few systems overloaded--
nothing serious.
I had to readjust my shields
during mid-flight--
almost lost my outer hull.
I'm sending you
the modifications.
My catapult is yours, Captain.
Good luck.
Get that data down to B'Elanna.
Tell her
to enhance our shields.
So we're going ahead
with the jump?
I want to run
a few more tests,
launch some probes,
but if it all checks out,
I see no reason not to.
I've received
the telemetry.
I'll take it
to Engineering.
I want you to add
a .03 variance
to these shield
modifications.
That'll disrupt
the emitters.
And you'll need
another six hours
to get them back
on line, I know.
Have you run this
by the Captain?
No...
and I'm not going to...
not yet.
She's pulling your leg.
It-it's got to be some kind
of Borg practical joke.
( sighs ):
She wasn't joking.
A secret mission?
Starfleet in league
with the Caretaker?
It's ridiculous.
"Ridiculous"?
Seven has some
compelling evidence.
Well, then,
let's go to the Captain,
get a straight answer.
"Good morning, Kathryn.
All systems
are operational.
"The crew's
in good health.
And by the way,
is it true
you've been lying
to us for five years?"
( sighs )
I'm not prepared
to make that accusation,
but I can't ignore
what I've heard, either.
So, what do you suggest?
I want you to delay
those shield modifications.
That'll give me time
to check Seven's database,
take a look
at the evidence myself.
( sighs )
The Captain asked me
to work with you on the shields.
That won't be
necessary, Ensign.
Oh, I don't mind.
Oh, you know how eager she is
to make that jump.
Harry, we're fine here.
"Too many cooks," Harry.
You know how it is.
We'll let you know
when we're done.
( sighs )
COMPUTER:
Download complete.
Seven of Nine
to Captain Janeway.
JANEWAY:
Go ahead.
I need to speak with you
in the Astrometrics Lab.
I'm on my way.
Computer, seal the door
and deactivate internal
sensors to this room.
Acknowledged.
Seven?
I believe Chakotay
and other members of your crew
are involved in
a conspiracy to resurrect
the Maquis Rebellion.
Did Chakotay put
you up to this?
Voyager and
the Federation itself
are in grave danger.
Go on.
I've concluded
that Chakotay intends
to use the catapult
to launch attacks
against Cardassian
and Federation starships.
Chakotay gave up
his allegiance
to the Maquis
a long time ago.
What you're saying
makes no sense.
Improbable as it may sound,
I found
compelling evidence
to support my theory.
In the months
before Voyager's arrival,
Neelix recorded
the sudden appearance
of 52 vessels...
including this one.
JANEWAY:
A Cardassian warship.
I've analyzed
the hull geometry
and warp signature.
It was one
of the same ships
that were pursuing Chakotay
and his crew
in the region known
as the Badlands.
It was pulled
into the Delta Quadrant
by the Caretaker
during that engagement.
According
to Federation records,
that same Cardassian warship
was found destroyed
in the Badlands.
The investigation revealed
that it was attacked
by the Maquis.
I believe that,
for some unknown reason,
the Caretaker had
sent this ship back
to the Alpha Quadrant,
and that Commander Chakotay
attacked the vessel
before it could reach
its destination.
He downloaded its computer core
and discovered the presence
of the Caretaker's Array.
He realized that
the Array could be used
by the Maquis as a weapon
to launch surprise attacks
against Cardassian
and Starfleet vessels.
Well, I commend you
for your imagination,
but Tuvok was a spy
on Chakotay's ship.
If your theory were true,
he would have known
about it.
He does. Tuvok has
been collaborating
with the Maquis resistance
all along.
That's not possible, Seven.
With Tuvok's assistance,
Chakotay plotted a course
toward the next likely
appearance of the Caretaker's
displacement wave,
offering his vessel as bait.
His ploy almost succeeded,
but the Caretaker was more
powerful than he anticipated.
His crew was taken captive.
A few days later, Voyager
arrived
and facilitated their escape.
Chakotay seized that opportunity
to make one last attempt
to gain control of the Array,
but then you gave the order
to destroy it.
Circumstantial evidence--
not proof.
Who carried out your order
to destroy the Array?
Tuvok.
Using what type of technology?
Tricobalt devices.
He set the yield
to 20,000 teracochranes.
It was enough to tear
an opening in subspace.
A cloaked ship locked on
to one of the reactors,
protecting it from
the blast and hiding it
from Voyager's sensors.
The reactor was retrieved
and carried by a series
of vessels,
until it was delivered
to Mr. Tash,
who was well-compensated
by Chakotay
to build the catapult.
He was waiting here
for Voyager,
so Chakotay could complete
the mission
he was forced to abandon
five years ago.
I'd be willing to consider
this theory of yours...
if I didn't know Chakotay
as well as I do.
There is no one on this ship
I trust more.
What you've done here
is build what we call
a house of cards.
Stardate 48658.
Commander Seska is revealed
to be a Cardassian spy.
She defects to the Kazon
and impregnates herself
with Chakotay's DNA.
Was he unaware of the procedure,
as he claims,
or were they working together
to create a new Kazon sect
to capture Voyager?
Stardate 49522.
Chakotay recommends
establishing
trade relations
with the Kolhari.
Their technology uses
tetryon power cells.
A simple diplomatic
overture,
or was he seeking a source of
energy for the catapult?
Stardate 49571...
Seven.
Naomi Wildman.
Where are you going?
That's not your concern.
What's wrong?
Your father was Ktarian.
So?
The Ktarians were officially
with the Federation,
but they sympathized
with the Maquis.
What are you talking about?
Who are you working for,
Chakotay or the Captain?
Seven...
Tell them it's too late. Go!
I picked up a power surge
coming from the Cargo Bay.
I detected
the same thing.
You think it's the
enhanced alcove?
Could be.
Let's take a look.
Are phasers standard
equipment on board now?
Must be.
The data buffer's
been activated.
I wanted to make
sure it wasn't
malfunctioning.
Well, you should
be careful.
Somebody might think
you were trying to
delete a few files.
Why would they
think that?
Some of those files
could contain
sensitive information.
If that's true,
somebody might think
you were trying to do
the same thing.
That catapult out there--
it's a powerful piece
of technology.
If the Maquis ever had access
to something like it,
they might
have been successful.
And if we had, your mission
to the Delta Quadrant
never would have gotten
off the drawing board.
What are you talking about?
The mission
you've been on for
the last five years.
My only mission is trying
to get Voyager home.
Seven showed me
the sensor records.
I saw
the tractor beam.
She showed me the same thing,
but she implicated you
in some kind of Maquis plot.
( sighs )
Same evidence.
Two different
theories.
It all started
with those damn photonic fleas.
She was downloading
Voyager's database...
KIM:
Bridge to Captain Janeway.
Go ahead, Harry.
I just picked up
an unauthorized launch
of the Delta Flyer.
Seven's at the helm.
Set a pursuit course.
Acknowledged.
Chakotay to the Doctor.
DOCTOR: Sick Bay here.
Get down to Cargo Bay 2.
Run a diagnostic
on Seven's alcove.
On my way.
I'm glad we got
that settled.
Likewise.
Chakotay...
let's keep this one
out of our logs, huh?
Gladly.
She's altering course,
heading for the catapult.
Maintain pursuit.
Open a channel.
No response.
Try to beam her out.
She's done something to
alter her bio-signature.
I can't get a lock.
Target her propulsion
and weapons.
Fire.
Our targeting scanners
are out of alignment.
She must have done it
before she took off.
She's charging weapons.
Keep trying.
Doctor to Captain Janeway.
Report.
Seven downloaded too much data
into her cortical implant.
She's trying to make sense
of more information
than she can process.
Understood. Beam me
onto the Delta Flyer.
I'm going with you.
No. I have a better chance
of getting through
to her alone.
This isn't part of
your mission, is it?
Is it part of yours?
Good luck.
Energize.
Captain.
You came here
hoping to stop me.
You'll fail.
Turn this ship around.
That's an order.
Your orders are irrelevant.
I'm no longer under
your command.
You deceived me.
There is no
conspiracy.
Maquis rebellion.
The Federation isn't
planning to invade
the Delta Quadrant.
I realize that, because
I finally uncovered
your true objective.
And what's that?
Me.
Stardate 32611.
The Federation
sends my parents
to study the Borg
collective.
They know my family
will be assimilated.
That was their intention.
Stardate 48317.
Voyager is sent
to the Delta Quadrant
with orders to retrieve me.
When they reach Borg space,
Captain Janeway negotiates
an alliance with
the collective
in exchange for information
regarding Species 8472.
They agree to give her
Seven of Nine.
Stardate 51030.
Janeway extracts
the implants from my body
to remove
any knowledge I have
of her agreement
with the Borg.
Stardate 53329.
Captain Janeway finalizes plans
to use the catapult
to deliver Seven of Nine
to the Alpha Quadrant,
where Starfleet will dissect
and analyze the drone
to gather tactical data
to fight the Borg.
I won't allow you
to complete your mission.
If necessary,
I'll destroy the catapult,
and myself.
You're right, Seven.
There is a
conspiracy here,
but I believe it's
a conspiracy of one.
I've got a theory
of my own.
Your modified alcove
threw your synaptic
patterns into chaos,
and your mind
can't make sense
of all the information,
so you're generating
theory after theory
in an attempt to bring
order to that chaos.
Your reasoning is flawed.
My alcove is functioning
perfectly.
What about you?
You're not a drone anymore.
You can't always predict
how Borg technology
will affect you.
You should be in Sick Bay,
not behind that
force field.
Let me help you.
No.
I don't believe you.
Of course you don't.
Anything I say gets woven into
your paranoid conspiracies,
but you should believe me,
Seven,
because I've never lied to you.
And I'm not lying to you now.
You have to put
your doubts aside
and trust me.
Stardate 51030.
Seven of Nine is severed
from the hive mind.
The Captain tells
her not to resist,
that she'll learn
to accept her humanity.
Seven complies
and slowly begins
to embrace her individuality.
Does she regret
that decision?
Stardate 51652.
The Captain encourages Seven
to develop her social skills.
Seven insists
it's a waste of time,
but after further requests,
she pursues it
and begins to develop her
first human friendships.
Did Janeway lead her astray?
Stardate 52840.
The Captain orders Seven
to study her parents' journals.
Seven claims
they're irrelevant,
but eventually
she reads them
and rediscovers part
of her own past.
Stardate 52841.
For the first time,
Seven tells the Captain...
"thank you."
It was Stardate 52842...
0600 hours in the Mess Hall.
We had just finished breakfast.
My mistake.
Stardate today.
Janeway beams aboard
the Delta Flyer.
She reminds Seven of the bond
that's grown between them.
Seven lowers
the force field
and she decides
to come home.
All I'm asking
is that you trust me again.
Delta Flyer
to Voyager.
Two to beam out.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
After further testing,
we activated the catapult
and were hurtled across
30 sectors of space.
In less than an hour,
we cut three years
off our journey.
I'm happy to say the Doctor
has repaired Seven of Nine's
cortical processor,
and she's returned to duty.
Guess who assimilated
three books and ten
reports in two days?
Naomi Wildman.
That's correct.
Are you taking your
new alcove apart?
Yes.
Why?
My attempt to download Voyager's
database failed.
Maybe you can fix it.
The alcove functioned
within expected parameters.
Unfortunately, I did not.
Three books
and ten reports
is impressive,
but quantity is less
relevant than quality.
You must be able
to interpret the data
and enjoy the process.
Regardless,
you require activities
other than assimilating
books and reports.
A game of Kadis-Kot,
for example.
When?
Go to the Mess Hall
and set up the board.
I'll join you when I'm finished.
I heard the strangest
rumor today.
Apparently, the Captain
and First Officer
almost came to blows.
Mutiny?
First Officer
walked the plank.
So I heard.
I don't believe
a word of it.
Me, neither.
Seven was
malfunctioning.
We don't have that excuse.
You're right.
We've been through too much
to stop trusting each other.
You didn't poison
the coffee, did you?
Not any more than I usually do.