( knock at door )
Just a minute.
I'll... I'll,
I'll be right there.
( knocking )
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Deanna!
Hello, Reg.
I'm so glad you could make it.
It's wonderful to see you.
Would it be all right
if I came inside?
Yeah. Of course.
Of course!
Come in,
come in.
Is-is there something
I can get you?
Some, um, some
coffee? Tea?
Oh, wait a minute.
Don't... don't tell me.
Chocolate ice cream.
You know me too well.
But just one scoop.
I'm watching my figure.
Why?! You...
you look lovely.
You always knew
how to flatter me.
Would you like me
to get it?
Get... get what?
The ice cream.
Right! Right!
No, no. No, no, no.
Come in, come in.
Sit down...
make yourself
comfortable.
It's a nice place.
Thanks.
One scoop of
chocolate ice cream.
Did you just move in?
No, no.
I've been here, uh...
almost two years.
I just haven't
had a chance to unpack.
Is everything
all right, Reg?
Of course.
Why, why wouldn't it be?
To be honest, you seem
a little on edge.
Do I? Oh, oh,
it's just that I'm...
I'm excited
to see you.
to see you, too.
I think Geordi's
a little disappointed
I didn't invite
him to come along.
Yes, I... well,
I-I was hoping to get...
get together with him, too,
uh, before the Enterprise
leaves orbit,
but I just wanted to spend
some time with you first.
That's all right,
isn't it?
Of course it is.
I hear you've been working
on the Pathfinder Project.
Well, I...
I was, uh...
I'm not anymore.
What happened?
Oh, uh...
nothing... really.
Just got to be
a lot of, uh...
pressure.
Well, hello!
Neelix!
Oh, he's not used
to company. Oh.
It's not polite
to eat our guest's food.
If you're hungry,
just say so.
Deanna, uh, Neelix.
Neelix?
That's an unusual name.
Maybe we should introduce him
to Data's cat, Spot.
( chuckles )
( sighs )
I have a feeling
you didn't ask me here
to reminisce.
Tell me what's wrong.
( sighs )
I've lost myself, Deanna.
Lost yourself?
In Voyager.
I've become obsessed
with Voyager.
Here you are
on shore leave,
and what do I do?
I lure you into
a counseling session.
Don't worry about that.
The important thing is
I'm here now,
and I want to help.
Thank you.
Now...
start at the beginning.
Has it ever occurred to you
that a tachyon beam
directed at a class-B
itinerant pulsar
could produce
enough gravimetric energy
to create an artificial
singularity?
I can't say it has.
It occurred to me,
but my supervisors thought
it was an abuse of MIDAS.
MIDAS?
The, uh, Mutara Interdimensional
Deep Space
Transponder Array.
Reg, you're losing me.
I'm sorry.
The beginning.
The beginning-- right.
Well, I suppose it all started
in the holodeck.
Doesn't it always?
( sighs ):
Go on.
Well...
I...
I was running
a few simulations.
Computer, boost the gain
on Voyager's transceiver
by 20 percent.
Transceiver gain is at maximum.
Apply a narrowband filter
to the signal processor.
Filter engaged.
MAN:
Voyager, come in.
Come in, Voyager.
This is Starfleet Command.
Voyager,
come in, Voyager.
Good. Good, good.
Now, lower the filter band
by .3 kilohertz.
Reg, what
are you doing?
Oh.
Uh, um, Pete.
I-I-I was just, uh...
Yes, running
another simulation.
I can see that.
What about
the transmitter diagnostics?
Right. The diagnostics.
You have finished them,
haven't you?
Uh... almost.
Almost isn't good enough.
We've got Admiral Paris
first thing in the morning.
Admiral Paris?
Don't tell me
you forgot.
Oh, no, of-of...
of course not.
I-I-I just got
the days mixed up.
Reg!
Computer, end program.
Now that I think about it,
it's a good thing
that Admiral Paris
is coming tomorrow.
We can brief
the Admiral
on my theory.
What theory?
I've been going over
the interstellar
phenomena forecasts
from Deep Space 9.
They are predicting, uh,
a class-B
itinerant pulsar
will pass within
four billion kilometers
of the MIDAS Array
in three days.
You think the pulsar
might damage the Array?
No, no. The
shields will hold.
Actually, I was thinking, uh,
we could use the pulsar
to our own advantage.
How?
Suppose...
suppose we instructed
the Array to direct
a tachyon beam
at the pulsar.
Theoretically, we could
produce a gravimetric surge
powerful enough to create
an artificial wormhole.
We could establish
two-way communication
with Voyager.
Reg, you're dreaming again.
No, no, I-I really think
this could work.
Based on
my simulations, that...
Based on your last series
of simulations,
we wasted six months
trying to develop
that transwarp probe.
This... this is
different. This...
Reg... I really appreciate
your imagination.
It's what makes you such
a valuable part of this team,
but I'm not about to tell
the Admiral
that we've found a way
for him to chat with his son
because of some
cockeyed theory that
only exists up here.
Now, please,
finish those diagnostics.
Yes, sir.
And, Reg, remember--
while the Admiral's here,
I do the talking.
You do the talking.
Understood.
Pete was only trying
to look out for me,
but I was sure
my plan would work.
I, I just couldn't
give it up.
Burning the midnight oil.
I-I finished, uh,
the diagnostics, sir.
Yes. I know.
I looked them over.
Good job.
Well, why don't you
call it a day?
I just, uh, have
a few more things
to take care of.
Well, see you
tomorrow, then.
Oh. Reg, why don't, um...
why don't you
drop by tonight
when you're through here?
"Drop by"?
Come to the house.
Have some coffee.
Angie's sister
is in from Boston.
I, uh...
I think she might like you.
I-I don't, I don't think I...
can, uh...
I'm spending the evening
with, um...
Neelix.
Correct me if I'm wrong, Reg,
but Neelix is your cat.
( sighs )
Well, if you change your mind.
Thanks.
I'll... I'll try.
But I couldn't leave,
not until I'd
strengthened my case
for accessing
the MIDAS Array.
The meeting
with Admiral Paris
was only 14 hours away,
and I hadn't come up
with anything.
Poring over the data
wasn't helping.
I decided that
what I needed was, um...
a little inspiration.
Computer...
activate hologrid
Mess Hall scenario
Barclay 11-Gamma.
( buzz of conversation )
Hey, Reg.
Warning. The
shark is circling.
( laughs ):
Let the games begin.
What'll it be, Reg?
The usual.
Computer,
one milk, warm.
Oh, thanks, Harry.
Just trying to get
on your good side,
so you'll go easy
on me tonight.
Ah, you know
what I always say--
if you can't stand
the heat...
Get out of the warp core.
Sit down, Lieutenant,
and give us mortals
a chance to get even.
That's an order.
If you insist, Commander,
but I think it's only fair to
warn you I have no intention
of letting my winning streak
come to an end.
Now, where's,
um, Tuvok?
He said it's illogical
to continue losing to
a clearly superior player.
Oh, that's too bad.
I love to watch
that Vulcan squirm.
Now, you all
know the rules.
Deuces, one-eyed jacks
and suicide kings are wild.
Five of a kind beats
a straight flush every time.
The man is
ruthless.
He's a killer.
Now, come on, guys.
You know it hurts me
to see you lose.
After all,
you are my best friends.
I'd hoped that
the poker game would
help calm my nerves,
so that I could get
a decent night's sleep
before the briefing,
but when I got home
that night,
I couldn't keep my mind
off of Voyager.
I needed to get back
to the holodeck.
( Barclay groaning )
That feels so good.
Therapeutic massage
can be an effective treatment
for insomnia, Lieutenant.
But we need to get to the cause
of your sleeplessness
if we're going to find
a more permanent solution.
It's just that every time
I-I close my eyes,
my mind starts to race.
Can you be more specific?
Well, I worry about the project.
Have I explored the problem
from every angle,
or is there something else
I should be trying?
Am I doing enough?
Hmm.
Acute work-related anxiety.
Perhaps I should speak
to the Captain about
reducing your schedule.
Oh, something tells me
she's not going to be able
to help.
You are an invaluable
member of this
crew, Mr. Barclay.
Thank you, Doctor.
It's nice to be appreciated.
Hmm.
Oh!
Turning in, Reg?
Yes, sir.
Hey, Reg.
For some reason, I never
slept in my apartment
as comfortably as I did
in my holographic quarters.
I suppose I felt more
at home on Voyager.
Mm-hmm.
Good morning, everyone.
Morning, Reg.
You're awfully chipper.
Ah... slept like a baby.
KIM:
Then maybe you've got
the energy to whip up
one of your famous
cheese omelets.
Oh, yeah.
I'm starved.
I'm sorry, guys.
I have a very important
briefing at 0900.
Just have time
for coffee.
Uh, don't forget
about tonight.
Uh... remind me.
You were supposed
to teach me how to
play velocity.
No. No way.
Reg and I have
a hoverball game scheduled.
Don't fight.
Plenty of me to go around.
Reg... I'm sorry
to bother you again,
but I'm still having trouble
with the warp core
recalibration.
It's no problem. I'll
stop by Engineering later
and talk you through it.
Thank you.
I really
appreciate it.
Velocity, hoverball,
warp core recalibrations?
Reg, I don't know
how you do it.
Let you in on a little secret.
There's two of me.
HARKINS:
The Delta Quadrant,
Sector 41751, Grid 9.
Voyager's Doctor
reported this
as the ship's position
when his program was
briefly transferred
to Starfleet two years ago.
Assuming they're still
on course for Earth,
we've been able to extrapolate
a range of likely trajectories.
Estimating an average
warp speed of 6.2
and accounting for various
astronomical obstacles...
we can reasonably assume
that Voyager
is now in one of
these three sectors.
Can we contact them?
As you know, we've been
working with the Vulcans
on the deployment
of the MIDAS Array.
Though we're still
in the testing phase,
we think it won't be
long before we can
use this technology
to send signals at
hyper-subspace speeds.
A message that would
normally take years
to reach its destination
could be received
by Voyager in
a matter of days.
Impressive.
Will they be able to respond?
No, sir,
but at least they'll know
we're still looking for them.
We'll send data
on the hyper-subspace
technology
and hope they can
eventually use it
to return the call.
Excuse me, Admiral Paris.
Lieutenant Barclay...
I-I'm sorry, Commander.
It's just that there may be
a way to establish, uh,
two-way communication
with Voyager.
Now is not the time.
It's all right,
Mr. Harkins.
Let the man speak.
I'm all ears, son.
Well, um...
Well, you see, there's a, uh,
a class-B
itinerant, uh, pulsar
uh, and... well-well,
as you probably know, s-sir,
uh, neutrino emissions, uh...
oh.
What I mean to say is
that with the Array,
we could open an artificial
uh, uh... a... sing...
a sing, uh, sing-singularity.
A wormhole?
Yes! Yes, sir.
We could use it as a conduit
to-to talk to Voyager.
I can't give you high marks
for clarity, Lieutenant,
but you've certainly got
my attention.
Is there any merit
to what he's saying?
Mr. Barclay has a tendency
to get ahead of himself, sir.
Unfortunately,
what he's suggesting
is beyond our abilities.
But you haven't even...
Mr. Barclay!
I know that I haven't
explained myself, uh, very well,
but with all due respect, sir,
what do we have
to lose by trying?
I think we're forgetting
that there are 150 people
stranded in
the Delta Quadrant.
I have a son
on that ship, Lieutenant.
I haven't forgotten that fact
for a single moment.
I'm sorry, sir.
I-I didn't, uh...
I didn't mean to...
Take the rest of
the day off, Reg.
But...
That was not a suggestion.
TROI:
How did you deal with
your feelings afterwards?
What do you mean?
Well... did you talk
to Commander Harkins
after the meeting...
apologize?
Well... no.
I wanted to, uh,
fine tune my plan,
so, I-I just went
right back to work.
Be more specific.
What exactly
did you do?
Well, I...
needed someone to, uh...
bounce ideas off of,
someone to help focus
my thoughts.
Sounds reasonable.
I suppose you... consulted
with some of your
Pathfinder colleagues.
Well...
not exactly.
You went back to the holodeck,
didn't you?
They're the only people
that I can talk to.
They're not people.
I know...
but they...
they help me with my work.
Poker, massages...
sleeping in
holographic
quarters?
Sounds more like escape
than work.
I can't concentrate
if I'm not relaxed.
Can't you relax
with your friends?
"Friends"?
Commander Harkins
invited you to his home.
You went
to the holodeck instead.
It's not what you're thinking,
Deanna.
This isn't a relapse
of my holo-addiction.
Okay.
Tell me how the holograms
helped you with your work.
Well, I talked to them
about my ideas.
I worked out
technical problems.
I need specifics
here, people.
Take us through it again,
Mr. Barclay,
one step at a time.
Maybe it'll
spark an idea.
We've got our itinerant pulsar.
We've got our interdimensional
transponder array.
How do we get
our wormhole?
This one could keep
us up all night.
Oh. We know we can produce
gravimetric energy,
but... can we do it
at levels high enough
to create the singularity?
We're talking
about a massive
subspace reaction.
Maybe...
that's the problem.
Reg?
Maybe we need
to think smaller.
You're losing me.
How much bandwidth
do we really need?
The average wormhole is huge,
but if we compressed
the datastream...
We wouldn't need
a conduit anywhere
near as big.
What's your idea?
A micro-wormhole.
Impressive.
You've outdone yourself
this time, Reg.
I'll still need, um...
help with the details.
JANEWAY:
Put together a team.
Use whatever
resources you need.
( sighs )
A power ratio
of approximately
60 terawatts
should do the trick.
You think that's enough?
Should be,
but then, we have
to compensate
for gravimetric
interference.
And how do
we do that?
I was thinking--
what if we applied
a narrowband filter
to the transponder signal?
Barclay strikes again.
What's going on here?
Commander...
Who's your
friend, Reg?
Yes, aren't you going
to introduce me?
Computer,
delete characters.
I thought I told you
to go home.
I was, uh...
working.
You call this work?
You've created holograms
of the Voyager crew.
Oh, it-it... it-it's
not what you think.
It's an interactive,
uh, diagnostic program.
I designed it to help
me... solve problems.
How long have you been in here?
Since the briefing.
The briefing ended
ten hours ago.
I... I know
that I embarrassed you
in front of the Admiral
and I am... I'm sorry.
I wanted to
refine my idea,
so that I could
present you
with a specific plan,
and I've done that, Pete.
You were right
about the wormhole idea
being too expansive.
So, I've-I've scaled it back...
All the extra time
you've been putting in--
if I checked
the holo-logs,
would I find
you've been spending
those hours in here?
Well, not-not all that
time.
How much of it?
Maybe, uh...
20 or...
30 hours a week.
Don't you think
that's a little excessive?
Uh, not if it helps us
contact Voyager.
Before I brought you
onto my team...
I reviewed your file.
You've struggled
with holo-addiction before.
From where I stand,
it looks like
you've had a relapse.
I-I know it-it may look
that way, but...
I think you need counseling.
What I need
is for you to pay attention
to my ideas!
I should've been paying
more attention
to your behavior.
I thought I was
being a friend
by giving you
some leeway.
I didn't realize how...
involved you've become
with Voyager.
Well, is it really so wrong?
Do you have any idea
what it must be like for them
to be stranded 60,000
light-years from home?!
Do you have any idea...
how lonely that must be?
I'm sorry, Reg...
but until you get some help,
you're off the project.
You-you can't do that.
You've given me no choice.
This hologrid and the lab
are officially
off limits.
Now, go home.
I won't leave--
not until you've heard
what I have to say.
Reg!
Don't make me call Security.
( buzzing )
What is it, Nicole?
He's still here.
You told him I have
a meeting scheduled at 1500?
Yes, sir.
He won't go away.
( sighing ):
Send him in.
Yes, sir.
Admiral, uh,
th-thank, thank you,
uh, for seeing me.
You're frightening
my secretary, Mr. Barclay.
You have five minutes.
Five minutes, right?
Sit down.
Uh, first... first,
I-I-I want to apologize
for speaking out of turn
yesterday.
I-it's only because I...
I, I care so much
about Voyager.
Yes, Commander Harkins
has informed me
about your attachment
to the crew.
I understand
you've been spending time
with a holographic re-creation
of my son, among others.
Frankly, I find that
rather disturbing.
Well, I understand
h-how you could see it that way,
but, uh, that does not negate
the fact that I have a plan
for communicating
with Voyager.
Commander Harkins doesn't seem
to think your plan is viable.
I have refined the idea.
I've simplified it.
All I'm asking for
is a chance to try.
And if I'm right, it could mean
a chance to talk to Tom.
In my opinion, Commander Harkins
removed you from the project
with good cause,
and that's his prerogative.
I won't let my personal feelings
interfere
with Starfleet procedure.
I... I've broken protocol
and I should be punished,
but the crew of
the Voyager shouldn't be,
and neither...
neither should you.
I just need access to the lab
for one more day.
After that, if I...
uh, if I'm wrong,
I'll resign my commission.
I'll order a review
of your findings.
If it's concluded
your ideas are valid,
I'll instruct Commander Harkins
to pursue it.
But...
I'm the one who knows...
That's the best
I can do, Mr. Barclay.
Good day.
So the meeting
went well.
No, no, no. It didn't,
not at all.
The Admiral said
he'd review
your findings.
Don't you see?
He was just trying
to get rid of me,
just like Harkins.
Try to relax.
Now you understand
why I need your help.
Yes, I do.
You-you have to call the Admiral
in your official capacity
as a Starfleet Counselor
and tell him that
I am psychologically fit
to return to work.
I can't do that.
( gasps ):
Why not?!
Look at yourself.
You're experiencing
acute anxiety,
sleeplessness, paranoia.
You did what you could.
Now it's time to let Starfleet
worry about Voyager.
We need to take care of you.
There is nothing
wrong with me!
You said yourself,
you've become
obsessed
with Voyager.
What if I have?
If an obsession helps me
to do my job better,
i-it's a sacrifice
I am willing to make.
A little instability
in exchange for contact
with a stranded starship.
Isn't Voyager
more important than my
psychological condition?
Voyager is important,
but so are you.
That ship...
that crew...
they're all I have.
Tell me why that is.
Ever... ever since
I-I left the Enterprise,
things haven't...
haven't been the same.
It's as if...
I lost my family.
So you created a new family
on the holodeck.
Only they're not real.
I didn't know how else...
how else to cope.
Do you remember when you first
came aboard the Enterprise?
You had trouble
fitting in, didn't you?
But after a while, you
started to make friends.
You can learn to do
the same thing here on Earth.
Oh, I... I don't know how.
We'll work on it together.
( stammering )
You're, you're scheduled
to depart tomorrow.
I've decided
to ask Captain Picard
for a temporary
leave of absence...
to spend some time
with an old friend.
Oh, Deanna, you...
you-you, you don't,
you don't have to do that.
Try and stop me.
( cat fussing )
I'm sorry, Neelix.
I have to leave.
( cat meows )
No, no,
you can't talk me out of it.
Authorization code required.
Barclay-alpha-one-seven-gamma.
Access denied. That code
has been de-authorized.
Computer, reenter
authorization code
Barclay-alpha-one-seven-gamma.
( beeping )
Access authorized.
Computer, interface
with the MIDAS Array.
Activate the control matrix.
Matrix activated.
Full power
to the graviton emitters.
Emitters powering.
Scan the area
surrounding the Array
for a class-B itinerant pulsar.
A pulsar has been detected
at coordinates 227 by 41 mark 6.
Good, good.
Direct a 60 terawatt
tachyon beam toward the pulsar.
Tachyon beam initiated.
How long
until levels are sufficient
to produce a gravimetric surge
of five million teradynes?
Approximately 17 minutes.
Computer, is there
a micro-wormhole present
at coordinates 343 by 27?
Scanning.
Affirmative.
I knew it.
Adjust the phase alignment
to direct
the wormhole's trajectory
to Delta Quadrant, Grid 9,
Sector 41751.
Trajectory established.
Open Starfleet Emergency Channel
and transmit
toward the singularity.
Channel open.
Starfleet Command
to USS Voyager.
Come in, Voyager.
Voyager, do you hear me?
This is
Lieutenant Reginald Barclay.
( door opens )
Step away from
the controls.
Pete.
I... I've sent a message.
Stand down, Mr. Barclay.
All right.
You win.
Computer...
transfer controls
to hologrid
program Barclay pi-three
and restrict access!
Stop him.
Stun him if you have to.
Tuvok, did you
see those two men?
I did not.
Well, they look like
Starfleet Security,
but they're not.
Intruders?
They're after me.
I need your help.
Tuvok to all hands.
Intruder alert.
Computer, locate
any unauthorized personnel
aboard Voyager.
Two unidentified humans,
Deck 4, Section 8.
Isolate them
with force fields.
Security to Commander Harkins.
We've been isolated
by force fields.
Can you shut down the program?
I'm working on it.
Access denied.
Hologrid controls
have been encrypted.
Harkins to Security.
I need reinforcements.
Computer, redirect
the wormhole's trajectory
to Delta Quadrant, Grid 11,
Sector 64238,
and retransmit the message.
Trajectory established.
Transmitting.
A wormhole?
What's going on?
I'm just trying
to help some friends.
Is there a response?
Negative.
Computer, redirect
the wormhole's trajectory.
Reg!
You'll have to
come with me, sir.
I'll cover for you.
Computer,
seal Jefferies Tube Door J53.
Computer, cut all power
to the hologrid.
Unable to comply.
Main power controls
have been encrypted.
Very clever, Reg.
Security to Commander Harkins.
We've lost him, sir.
I've got an idea.
I'm coming in.
I know you.
You're Reg's friend.
You've got something to do
with what's going on here,
don't you?
Computer, disengage
primary coolant system.
Are you crazy? That'll cause
a warp core breach!
Exactly.
Mr. Barclay,
I want an explanation
for what's going on
aboard my ship.
I'm looking after Voyager's
best interests, Captain.
You're just going to have
to trust me on that.
You've never given me
any reason to doubt you before.
Computer, redirect
the wormhole's trajectory
to Delta Quadrant,
Grid 10, Sector 3658
and retransmit the message.
Trajectory established.
Transmitting.
Who are you trying
to contact, Reg?
Warning.
Warp core breach in 45 seconds.
Bridge to Engineering.
Report.
Shut down the program, Reg.
Janeway to Security.
Intruders on the Bridge.
Computer,
establish a force field
around the science station.
Warning.
Warp core breach in 30 seconds.
Harry, get down
to Engineering.
Seal that breach.
Force fields aren't going
to help you, Reg. It's over.
But this is my last chance.
Warp core breach in 20 seconds.
Captain to all hands.
Abandon ship.
Warp core breach in ten seconds.
One way or another,
this program's going to end.
...seven, six...
Good-bye, Captain.
...four...
Computer, end program.
...two...
I'm ready
for my lesson.
I've concluded that
teaching you to sing
is an inefficient
use of my time.
But I... I've...
I've been practicing.
In your case,
practice is irrelevant.
Your vocal chords
are incapable
of producing
basic diatonic tones,
not to mention your
rhythmic shortcomings.
I sound so good
in the sonic shower.
Perhaps you should
confine your efforts
to that location.
( console beeping )
Astrometrics to the Bridge.
Go ahead, Seven.
I've detected what appears
to be a micro-wormhole
at coordinates 194.6 by 35.
A micro-wormhole?
I believe a message is being
transmitted through it...
on a Starfleet
Emergency Channel.
Let's hear it, Harry.
BARCLAY ( staticky ):
Starfleet Command
to USS Voyager.
( static drowns out message )
Try applying a narrowband filter
to the signal processor.
Do you hear me?
This is
Lieutenant Reginald Barclay.
That's it.
Whoever
this Barclay is,
he stopped
transmitting.
TUVOK:
The micro-wormhole is collapsing
at a rate of .2 percent
per second.
That doesn't
give us much time.
To do what?
To send a message
back through
and hope Mr. Barclay
is listening.
It should have worked.
I don't understand
why it didn't.
There you are.
I've reviewed
Mr. Barclay's plan.
I think it's
worth an attempt.
He's already tried, sir,
without your authorization.
It didn't work.
I'm sorry to hear that.
So am I, sir. I appreciate
your confidence in me,
but I... I don't deserve it.
What would you like me
to do with him, Admiral?
He broke into the lab,
accessed the MIDAS Array,
resisted arrest.
You've put me
in a difficult position, son.
I was hoping
that we'd be able to...
( alarm beeping )
We're receiving
a transmission.
From where?
Coordinates 343.6 by 27.
The wormhole.
JANEWAY ( staticky ):
Starfleet Command, come in.
Voyager.
Reg, give me a hand
clearing up the signal.
Lower the filter band
by .3 kilohertz.
This is Captain Kathryn Janeway.
Do you read me?
I think
she's talking to you.
Captain...
this is
Lieutenant Reginald Barclay
at Starfleet Command.
It's good to hear
your voice, Lieutenant.
We've been waiting a long time
for this moment.
The feeling is mutual.
Unfortunately, the
micro-wormhole is collapsing.
We have only
a few moments.
Understood.
We are transmitting
our ship's logs, crew reports,
and navigational records
to you now.
Acknowledged,
and we're sending you
data on some new
hyper-subspace technology.
We're hoping, eventually,
to use it
to keep in regular contact,
and we're including some
recommended modifications
for your com system.
We'll implement them
as soon as possible.
Uh, there's someone else here
who would also
like to say something.
This is Admiral Paris.
Hello, sir.
How are your people holding up?
Very well.
They're an
exemplary crew,
your son included.
Tell him... tell him I miss him,
and I'm proud of him.
He heard you, Admiral.
The wormhole is collapsing.
I want you all to know
we're doing everything we can
to bring you home.
JANEWAY:
We appreciate it, sir.
Keep a docking bay open for us.
We hope to...
( transmission cuts off )
That's it.
They're gone.
You did it, Reg.
I'm sorry I doubted you.
Why the long face, Mr. Barclay?
Because...
because it's over, sir.
No, Lieutenant.
I'd say that Project Voyager
is just beginning...
thanks to you.
Anyone know
this Barclay?
I took the liberty
of reviewing his
personnel file.
He's had a rather
colorful career,
not to mention an
unusual medical history.
He's recovered
from a variety
of maladies
including
transporter phobia
and holo-addiction.
Well, whatever his problems,
he certainly came
through for us.
Starfleet should
give him a promotion.
I've finished
analyzing the data
Mr. Barclay sent.
The hyper-subspace
technology is promising.
I believe we can look forward
to future communications
with Earth.
Well, that calls
for a toast.
Care to do the honors, Tom?
To... my dad.
It's nice to know
he's still there.
And to the newest
honorary member
of the Voyager crew,
Reginald Barclay,
whoever you are.
Hear, hear.
To Mr. Barclay.
TROI:
Congratulations.
Well, I'm not... not sure
I deserve congratulations.
Why not?
It's quite an
accomplishment.
I, I couldn't have done it
without your help.
What did Commander Harkins
have to say about it?
Well, I think...
I think he was pleased.
Why wouldn't he be?
You're quite a catch.
Well, not everyone
would want his sister-in-law
to date someone
with my history.
It's a new era.
So, tell me
all about the lucky lady.
I want details.
Well, her name is Hope.
You're kidding.
No, and-and-and...
she loves cats.