( whistle blows )
( sheep bleating )
Good day to you.
( sighs )
Good morning, Tom.
Good morning, Grace.
So, where are
you heading?
Uh, Sullivan's.
Care to join me?
Oh, I wish I could,
but there's a bit of a problem.
Oh, really?
Well, you see,
Tommy, me boy,
the good Lord blessed me
with a fine wife.
I'll never forget
the day I met her.
I was on me way
to the fair in Dooleen...
or was it Kilkee?
There's some fine
trout fishing
to be had in Kilkee
this time of year.
Who said anything
about trout?
Timothy Ryan,
God rest his soul.
He was one
for the trout.
The poor man's
been dead a fortnight.
Some say he had
the croup,
but don't you believe it.
The widow Moore
gave him the evil eye.
And... your point?
Me wife and I--
well, we've hit
a bit of a rough patch.
A better woman never walked
the face of the earth.
She threw you
out again.
With nothing but the clothes
on me back.
How much?
A shilling or two
should suffice.
Keep the change.
God bless you,
Tommy, me boy.
( chuckles )
( sighs )
Harry...
weren't you supposed
to meet me at Sullivan's?
Oh, sorry,
I got distracted
by the, uh, scenery.
This is Maggie.
We've met.
Could you excuse us?
Charmed to have
met you, Harry.
Charmed.
What's the hurry?
A word to the wise--
stay away from
Maggie O'Halloran.
She's promised
to a pig farmer
with a very
large rake.
Well, does she have
a sister?
Wooden teeth.
Oh, nothing
a little adjustment
to the holo-matrix
wouldn't fix.
No, no, I'm not
changing a thing.
Fair Haven is perfect
just the way it is.
Tommy boy, you forgot
the leprechauns.
( chuckles ):
Yeah. No.
No leprechauns, no
aliens, no starships.
I want this to be
a place where the
crew can unwind.
( bell rings )
Morning, lads.
Ah, heard any good
confessions lately?
Doctor/patient confidentiality,
Mr. Paris.
Harry hasn't seen
Sullivan's yet.
Do you care to join us?
Don't mind if I do.
I'll need to leave
no later than 1300 hours.
Medical emergency?
Not exactly. I'm
working on my homily
for Sunday's mass,
and I expect
both you sinners...
to be in attendance.
He's kidding, right?
You wanted
authenticity.
( sighs )
Everybody, place your bets!
Three bob on Liam.
Three bob it is.
Five shillings
on Liam.
You're going to hurt
Harry's feelings.
Oh, very well.
Two shillings
on Mr. Kim,
and I'll pray
for a miracle.
Excuse me, Father,
but I needed
a bit of counsel.
I'm off duty right now.
But I've broken the
Fifth Commandment again.
Say ten "Our Fathers"
and call me in the morning.
Oh, thank
you, Father.
Gentlemen.
( crowd shouting )
Come on, come on, Mr. Kim.
Show him what for.
You can do it.
What'll it be?
I'm looking
for some friends of mine.
Well, we're all
friends here.
Well, then,
have you seen Tom Paris?
He's right over there
with young Harry.
Poor sod.
I'm afraid no
one's whipped Liam
in three years.
There's a first time
for everything.
An optimist,
are you?
A realist.
Come on, Ensign, try!
Try!
Come on, me boy,
push, push!
I'm trying!
Come on! Try harder!
You got him! You got him, lad!
You got him!
( grunting )
What?!
What in God's name...?!
Come on, Liam, push!
Yes! Yes!
I knew you could
do it, Ensign.
So, this is the program
I've been hearing
so much about.
Welcome,
weary traveler.
You have outdone yourself
this time.
Everything is authentic,
except for one tiny detail.
Oh?
The harp on the sign--
it's backwards.
Oh. Everybody's a critic.
As I recall, the Captain
is quite an aficionado
of Irish history.
I hate to break
up the party,
but we have some
business to attend to.
There's a neutronic
wavefront approaching,
class-9.
Class-9?
Sorry, boys,
duty calls.
Uh, "wavefront"?
Now, what in the name
of God is that?
Um, a wee bit
of bad weather.
Oh.
SEVEN:
Borg classification
3472,
particle density
anomaly.
Where'd it come from?
I believe it was formed
by the collision
of two neutron stars.
The wavefront is traveling
at a velocity of 200,000
kilometers per second,
and it extends
for 3.6 light-years.
How long before
it hits?
Approximately 15 hours.
We're already
feeling its effects.
The neutron radiation
is disrupting plasma flow.
We can't jump to warp.
Impulse power won't be enough
to outrun that thing.
Then we'll have
to ride it out.
We'll generate an
inverse warp field
and drop anchor.
That should protect us
from the turbulence.
What about the radiation?
It'll only get worse.
Have the Doctor
prepare inoculations
for the crew.
Go to Yellow Alert.
Tom, B'Elanna,
get started
on converting
the warp core.
PARIS:
Yes, ma'am.
Let's batten down
the hatches.
Captain.
Just burning
the midnight oil.
Midnight's
come and gone.
Then it's time
for a break.
Do you mind?
I could use
the company.
This approaching
wavefront--
it's bringing back
some unpleasant memories.
How so?
You know I grew up
on a farm in Indiana.
We used to have some
terrible thunderstorms
during the summer months.
At the first bolt
of lightning,
I'd bolt under the bed.
We had some pretty nasty weather
on Talax, too.
I always enjoyed
a good ion storm.
Give me clear skies any day.
Well, now that
you bring it up, uh,
I am concerned
with keeping up morale
over the next few days.
The crew is not used
to sitting still.
Suggestions?
Everyone seems to love
Fair Haven.
I was thinking we might initiate
an open-door protocol
on the holodeck
and keep the program running
24 hours a day, let people
come and go as they please.
Permission granted.
Fair Haven's just become
our port in the storm.
( sighs )
I'm, uh, heading
down there myself,
if you'd like
to join me.
There's a charming
little inn
called The Ox
and Lamb.
The owner
offered to share
some of his recipes.
No, thanks.
I still have work to do.
Okay.
( chair rattles )
What'll it be?
A cup of tea would be nice.
I just made one.
Cream?
Please.
So, what brings you
to Fair Haven, Miss...?
Kathryn. I'm just
passing through...
on my way home.
How long have you been
on the road?
Five years,
almost six.
You must be homesick.
No.
Sometimes. Thank you.
"Cead mil failte."
Translation?
"A hundred thousand
welcomes."
It's an old Irish saying.
We're all friends here.
I had an aunt who used to
have a saying like that.
"A stranger is a friend
you just haven't met yet."
Definitely Irish.
She had an Irish
temper, too.
She and my uncle had
a place not far from here
in County Clare.
Ah... then you're
closer to home
than you think,
Katie O'Clare.
( sets spoon down )
You know, it's later
than I thought, and I've
kept you long enough.
Oh, now, stay awhile.
Didn't your auntie teach you
that it's impolite to leave
without playing a game of rings?
I really can't,
but thanks for the tea.
Afraid you'd lose?
I rarely lose.
Prove it.
One game.
I'll set them up.
Another ringer.
Well, I'm not surprised.
You stepped
over the beer stain.
I did not.
You did, too,
by half a boot,
and then you moved back,
hoping I wouldn't notice.
These boots are half a size
too large, so in reality,
my toes never crossed the line.
Your turn.
For luck.
Getting sweet with the rings
isn't going help you.
We'll see.
Damn!
Devil won't help you, either.
Well, maybe rings
aren't my forte after all.
Would you care
to arm wrestle?
That's not
a woman's game, Katie.
You could get hurt.
I'm stronger
than I look.
Ah!
( laughs )
Now, that's quite
a grip you have.
Not bad yourself.
( grunting )
I couldn't help but notice
that you have your leg
braced against the bar.
Well, how else do you
expect me to win?
( grunting )
Well, will we call it
a draw?
Sounds good to me.
( groaning )
We run a foot race
down to the station and back?
( laughing )
It's good to make
a new friend.
You have a nice way
about you.
"Flattery's the
food of fools."
Another pearl of wisdom
from your auntie?
No. Jonathan Swift.
Swift? Never heard of him.
He was an author.
I was never one
for reading.
Well, that's too bad.
Some of the greatest
writers in the
world are Irish.
Well, they say that Dr. Gilroy
has a library of books,
and, well, next time
I see him,
I'll ask him can I borrow
one or two.
Good mornin'.
Oh, my God, will you
look at the time?
Frannie, come here.
There's someone
I want you to meet.
Katie O'Clare,
this is my wife,
Francis.
Pleased to meet you.
I hope Michael hasn't been
bending your ear
all night long.
My ear, my elbow...
We were arm wrestling.
Mmm, such a gentleman.
Well, thank you very much
for your hospitality,
and now I really
must be leaving.
And, uh, drop in again
before you leave town.
I will!
If you experience
any dizziness,
report to Sick Bay
immediately.
Thank you.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I believe it's
afternoon-- oversleep?
Holodeck.
Fair Haven?
Welcome, weary traveler.
Even I have to admit--
Mr. Paris' latest effort
is quite a tour de force.
Ooh, high praise
from a hologram.
Oh, I was thinking,
Captain--
now that we've got
this open-door policy,
maybe I could expand Fair Haven
into Holodeck 2.
It would give me some room
to create the seacoast.
By all means.
Speaking of revisions,
I was hoping I could give
my character a more active role.
In the period you've created,
the village priest
was the most prominent
member of the community,
held in the highest regard.
You know, that's
a great idea, Doc.
We could send
Father Mulligan
on a retreat
to a nearby monastery,
where he takes
a vow of silence
and never speaks again.
Try it!
And you'll be saying
"Hail Marys"
till St. Patrick's Day.
( both laughing )
Time?
30 seconds.
Let's see it.
All hands,
this is the Captain.
Secure your stations
and brace for impact.
We've cleared the leading edge.
Turbulence is decreasing.
Shields are holding.
Damage?
We've got a ruptured
plasma conduit, Deck 9.
Send a repair team.
Maintain Yellow Alert.
Let's hope that was
the worst of it.
Captain's Personal Log.
It's been ten hours
since the storm hit.
We estimate
another three days
before we're clear of it.
The crew's in good spirits,
and many of them
have taken the opportunity
to visit Fair Haven.
I met an interesting man
there, and for a while,
I almost forgot
he was a hologram.
We weren't exactly
compatible.
Then again, Mr. Paris
didn't program him
to my specifications.
Computer, display Fair Haven
character Michael Sullivan.
Adjust his parameters to
the following specifications.
Give him the education
of a 19th century...
third-year student
at Trinity College.
( computer beeps )
COMPUTER:
Modification complete.
Now... access the character's
interactive subroutines.
Make him more provocative.
Specify.
Give him a more
complicated personality.
Specify.
( sighs )
More outspoken...
more confident,
not so reserved...
and make him more curious
about the world around him.
Modification complete.
Good. Now...
increase the character's
height by...
three centimeters.
Remove the facial hair.
No... no,
I don't like that.
Put some back--
about two days' growth.
Better.
Oh, one more thing.
Access his interpersonal
subroutines...
familial characters.
Delete the wife.
Modification complete.
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Sullivan.
Are you ill,
Commander?
I am experiencing
a slight loss of equilibrium
and some gastrointestinal
distress.
Space sickness?
Unlikely. I'm not prone
to that condition.
Perhaps you should
go to Sick Bay.
I'll be fine.
KIM:
I'm telling you,
we should add more fog.
Fog is depressing.
It's authentic!
It's dangerous!
( sighs ):
All right, we could add
a lighthouse.
It's Fair Haven, Harry.
Sunshine.
Tuvok, what do you think:
Irish seacoast--
fog or no fog?
I have no opinion.
He hasn't visited our
little paradise yet.
Nor do I intend to.
KIM:
I think you'd
like it, Commander.
It's a great place
to meditate.
Imagine yourself
sitting
high on a bluff
overlooking the ocean.
Salt air...
the rhythm of the waves
rising and crashing
against the rocks...
a tiny fishing boat
bobbing on the
water below...
up and down,
up and down.
I get the idea, Ensign.
Thank you.
Mutton, creamed cabbage
or blood pudding?
Explain.
I'm preparing
a traditional Irish meal
at The Ox and Lamb
this afternoon,
and I cannot decide
on a main course.
Blood pudding--
you can't lose.
Well, that was
my first choice, too,
but replicating
the lamb's intestines--
it-it could be tricky,
and every time
I try to heat the blood,
it coagulates in the milk.
If you'll excuse me.
I think I will consult
the Doctor.
( dogs barking )
( sheep bleating )
Excuse me, ma'am.
Hmm?
Have you seen
Michael Sullivan?
Oh, you might try
the pub.
I just came
from there.
Oh, then he'll be
at the train station.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Sure.
Excuse me, sir.
Is the train to Galway
running on time?
Um... I'm afraid
you've just missed it.
Have a seat.
Wait for the next one.
Do you know Jane Eldon?
Eldon. No,
I've never met her.
Well, I'd be terrified
if you had.
She's been
dead 70 years.
( laughing )
No, I was, uh...
I was thinking
about her poetry.
It's too pastoral
for my taste.
Don't you agree?
I'm not familiar
with her work.
Really?
Well, what about
Sean Gogarty?
They have similar
rhyming schemes.
You've some
catching up to do.
( chuckling )
Well, I'm here
every afternoon.
You should join
me sometime.
I tried talking
poetry with Seamus,
but all he can do
is recite limericks.
I'd love to.
Strange place
to read, though.
Not at all.
I love the sound of the
trains coming and going.
Gets me thinking
about places
I'd like to visit.
Have you traveled
much yourself?
As a matter of fact...
But there's one place
I haven't been yet--
Castle O'Dell.
It's a steep climb,
but from the top
of the battlement,
you can see all
the way to Dublin.
We'd better
be moving.
They say when the sun
goes down,
the King of the Faeries
reclaims the castle.
Maybe he'll invite
us to supper.
Eh, you'll be dining alone,
without me.
One taste
of the faeries' banquet,
and you'll never return
to this world.
Oh, don't tell me you
believe those stories.
Believe? No.
But I do respect them.
Can I ask you something,
Katie?
Please.
Have you a man
waiting for you at home?
No.
Are you looking for one?
( laughing )
Why, do you
have somebody?
In Fair Haven?
Not unless you fancy
a pig farmer.
Oh, not my type.
Well, what about
a barkeep
who reads poetry
in strange places?
Captain?
I thought that was you.
Just getting
in the spirit.
I can see that.
I don't believe we've met.
Sullivan.
Michael Sullivan.
Chakotay.
That's a fine tattoo.
Are you off a ship?
You could say that.
We're on the way up
to the old castle.
You're welcome
to come with us.
Thanks, but, um...
I'm meeting Neelix
at The Ox and Lamb.
You two have fun.
Is it my imagination,
or did he call you Captain?
Did he?
Looks like the worst
is yet to come.
Commander?
I just came
from Astrometrics.
Seven's found an increase
in the neutronic gradient
at the trailing edge
of the wavefront.
It's going to be
a rough ride when it hits.
We've still
got two days.
Start working on a
new shield modulation.
Yes, ma'am.
That could explain
my recent space sickness.
Vulcan physiology
is highly sensitive
to neutronic gradients.
You'd make a good barometer,
Tuvok.
Every time you get queasy,
we go to Red Alert.
Thanks for your report,
Commander.
Don't mention it.
Hills Most Green,
Hearts Unseen.
Yes. Jane Eldon.
Catching up on
a little reading.
Those hills and hearts
wouldn't happen to be
in Ireland?
You can wipe
that smirk off your face.
It's not what you think.
I wasn't thinking anything,
but now that you mention it...
I have an interest
in Irish culture.
It's understandable.
They've produced
great writers
for hundreds of years...
not to mention great bartenders.
He's a hologram.
I couldn't help but notice--
he seemed a little taller
than the last
time I saw him.
Yes, I made
a few modifications.
In the interest
of Irish culture?
Exactly.
You seemed embarrassed
when I ran into you.
There was no
reason to be.
It was nice to see you
having a little fun.
He is rather charming,
isn't he?
Too bad he's made
of photons and force fields.
I never let that
stand in my way.
( Irish jig playing )
The boys are
getting tired.
Them or you?
Faster, boys!
( tempo increases )
( clapping and clamoring )
( music ends, applause )
Computer...
remove all characters
except for Michael Sullivan.
Can I ask you
something, Katie?
Please.
Would you mind
if I kissed you?
( laughs )
I might even kiss you back.
There's no point in
waiting any longer,
is there?
Oh, I think
I've waited long enough.
Is there
something wrong?
( whispers ):
No.
Computer, recycle.
( door chimes )
Come in.
I thought you'd
like to know
we've organized a rings
tournament tonight
at Sullivan's.
Thanks, Neelix,
but I have work to do.
The Doctor's going to sing
something called "Danny Boy",
and Mossie Donegan's promised
to bring his talking pig.
Well, let's just say
I'd rather stick to
reality right now.
1900 hours...
if you change your mind.
Thank you.
Saints preserve us.
I possess superior
hand/eye coordination.
That's not all
that's superior.
The lily and the rose
are staging
a competition
on your face.
Clarify.
The fullness
of your lips
and the paleness
of your cheeks--
it's enough to
make a man faint.
Then, in that case,
perhaps we should sit down.
I don't believe it.
It's called
"old-world charm," Harry.
What'll it be,
gentlemen?
Nothing for me.
"Temperance
is a virtue."
Where's Michael?
Over there.
That's strange.
I programmed him
not to drink.
Must be a glitch
in his subroutine.
Are these seats taken?
Sit anywhere
you like.
( clears throat )
( sighs ):
Vile.
It's been 15 years
since I touched the stuff.
You making up
for lost time?
I was hoping
it might ease the pain.
Are you in discomfort?
Agony's more like it.
How could you do this to me,
Lord?
Why don't you ask him?
You've got his ear,
don't you?
Well...
Three days...
the happiest three days
of my life.
I was a fool to think
she felt the same.
I was such a fool!
SEAMUS:
Aw, sit down, Sullivan.
Shut your mouth, man,
or I'll shut it for you.
Oh, you will,
will you?
Hey, hey, hey...
take it easy.
Um... why don't you tell us
what happened?
( sighs ):
We...
we spent a perfect day
together by the lake.
I drifted off to sleep,
and... when I woke up,
she was gone.
Where is she, Tom?
Who?
Katie O'Clare--
who else?
Katie O'Clare?
Your friend.
Um...
are you sure
you didn't...
uh... misinterpret
her interests?
I mean, we're
all friends here.
Maybe she was just
being friendly.
You calling me a liar?
N-no, no,
not at all.
I thought...
Katie and me were in love.
I may have to do
some reprogramming...
What's the matter?
You don't think
I'm good enough for her?
No, I-I didn't
say that.
Well, tell me
where she's gone.
I don't know.
Well, I think you do!
( grunting )
Gentlemen, please!
"Love thy neighbor."
Let's see...
I remember
trying to reach the
holodeck controls.
Then, uh, somebody
grabbed my leg.
Maybe it was
the talking pig.
( chuckles ):
If it was, he had
one hell of a left hook.
What's all this?
I'm afraid there's
been some trouble
in paradise--
an altercation in the pub
this afternoon.
Several crewmen
were injured.
Nothing serious.
Arm wrestling get
out of hand, boys?
Not exactly.
It was Michael Sullivan,
Captain.
He was...
( clears throat )
...looking for someone.
Why don't we...
take a little walk?
Let me guess--
that someone is me.
I don't mean to
pry, Captain,
but we've got a
broken-hearted hologram
who believed that the
two of you were in love.
Oh, I was sure he'd be
on to the next lass by now.
I hope he's all right.
Far from it.
The fight spilled
out onto the street.
Before long, he'd
climbed up a tree
and began shouting
your name.
Mr. Neelix managed
to... talk him down.
It could be a malfunction
in his behavioral subroutines.
I've already checked that.
His subroutines are fine.
But I did notice
you've made
quite a number
of alterations
to his program.
Minor improvements.
To make him more appealing?
You're starting
to pry, Doctor.
I apologize for
overstepping my bounds,
but I'm worried
about you.
Michael Sullivan
is a hologram.
His broken heart can be
mended with the flick
of a switch.
Your feelings,
however,
are a little more...
complicated.
I'm not going to be
climbing any trees,
if that's what you're
worried about.
If you decide
you want to talk,
I've been hearing a lot
of confessions lately.
Let me know.
You want a confession,
Doctor?
All right.
I've become
romantically involved
with a hologram,
if that's possible.
Tell me what
happened.
Oh, you know the story--
girl meets boy;
girl modifies
boy's subroutines.
Did you have
intimate relations?
That's none
of your business.
Let's just say it was
a memorable three days.
I don't see
the problem.
Don't you?
Michael Sullivan
is exactly my type--
attractive,
intelligent.
We share
the same interests,
and if there's something
I don't like,
I can simply change it.
I've noticed that
humans usually try
to change the people
they fall in love with.
What's the difference?
In this case, it works.
We had a picnic by the lake
yesterday afternoon.
Michael drifted off
to sleep.
His head was lying
on my shoulder,
and I remember thinking,
"This is close to perfect."
Then he began to snore.
Did I nudge him
with my elbow,
hoping he'd roll over
and stop?
Did I whisper in his ear
to wake him? No.
Why bother, when I could
simply access the computer
and alter
his vocal algorithms?
And that's exactly
what I was about to do,
when I realized
that everything around me
was an illusion,
including him, so I left.
Oh, I almost wrote him a note
to say good-bye.
Could you believe that--
a "Dear John" letter
to a hologram?
I understand your
trepidation...
but you're
the Captain.
You can't have
a relationship
with a member
of your crew.
They're all your
subordinates.
So where does
that leave you--
the occasional
dalliance with
a passing alien?
Voyager could be in
the Delta Quadrant
for a very long time.
A hologram may be
the only logical
alternative.
He's not real.
He's as real
as I am.
Photons and force fields;
flesh and blood--
it's all the same,
as long as your
feelings are real.
He makes a joke;
you laugh.
Is that an illusion?
He says something
that makes you think.
Does it matter how his
molecules are aligned?
Did it ever occur to you
that it's not
just a question
of whether or
not he's real?
What do you mean?
I think you should
stop trying to control
every aspect of
this relationship.
Romance is born
out of differences
as well as
similarities...
out of the unexpected
as well as the familiar.
Maybe I just needed
to be sure...
he'd love me back.
But isn't that the
risk you always take,
hologram or not?
All I know is...
Michael Sullivan was
up in that tree,
shouting your name.
I've never been afraid
of taking risks.
Then perhaps
next time,
you should just...
let him snore.
The neutronic gradient's
rising--
30 million terajoules...
40 million.
Shields.
Holding.
60 million.
Torres to Bridge. The inverse
warp field's destabilizing.
We're losing our anchor.
Acknowledged. How long
before we're clear?
At least
another five minutes.
That's about four
minutes too long.
The gradient's rising fast--
90 million.
Stabilizers are off-line.
Thrusters.
No effect.
Shields are failing.
How close are we
to the perimeter?
A thousand kilometers,
but we're being pulled along
with the storm.
What have you got in mind?
The deflector beam--
we might be able
to cut a path
through the wavefront.
It's possible,
but we'd have to route
all available power
to the emitters.
That won't be enough.
Primary systems are down.
Then transfer all
secondary power sources--
transporters,
replicators, holodecks.
Captain, there's not enough time
to go through the hologrid
shutdown sequence.
We'd lose most of Fair Haven.
Do it.
Hull fractures,
Decks 6 and 7.
You've got
all the secondary power, Tuvok.
Is that enough?
Negative.
Siphon energy
from the plasma network--
every last deciwatt!
Deflector beam active.
We're approaching
the perimeter.
500 kilometers...
400...
Deflector output is dropping.
Give him everything we've got--
life support,
environmental control.
Scrape the residual ions
off the sonic showers
if you have to.
( sighing )
Doesn't look good, Tom.
With this much
photonic decay,
we'll be able to save five,
maybe ten percent.
So much for the
luck of the Irish.
It might be easier
to start from scratch.
It wouldn't
be the same.
It's like trying
to rewrite a novel
after the only copy
of the data file's
been deleted.
All the details,
the nuances--
they're all gone.
Morning, lads.
Hey, Seamus.
Looks like
a storm brewing.
A storm?
Heading in from the west.
Could be a big one.
Oh... you're right.
I don't suppose
you could spare
a shilling or two?
Me wife and I made up
last night,
and I wanted
to buy her a new parasol.
The grid's
destabilizing.
We'd better get started
on those repairs.
So, what do we try and save?
The Ox and Lamb? The church?
Maggie O'Halloran?
There's someone
I should talk to
before we decide.
( door chimes )
Come in.
Fair Haven didn't fare
too well.
I'll break the news to the crew.
With your permission,
I'd like to try
to reconstruct the program.
How long will it take?
Six or seven weeks.
Harry tells me that
we should be able to save
about ten percent
of the existing elements.
I thought you might have
a suggestion or two.
Computer,
is Fair Haven character
Michael Sullivan still intact?
Affirmative.
Activate him.
Hello.
You disappeared
on me, Katie.
I woke up,
and you had gone.
I had some
thinking to do.
Are you done?
( laughs ):
Yes.
I'm leaving Fair Haven.
Why?
Because.
That's not a very good reason.
The situation is complicated.
Another man?
No.
Your friends...
they don't approve of me?
They think you're charming.
Are you not ready
to settle down yet?
I'm as ready as I'll ever be.
You're not making any sense.
No, I guess I'm not.
Well, I have a feeling
that, uh, you won't
be forgetting us that easily.
Fair Haven has that effect
on people.
But there's one thing
I want you to know.
I love you, Katie.
( sighs )
I might actually
be passing this way
in, uh... six or seven weeks.
Maybe I'll stop by the pub.
See that you do.
Oh, computer,
end program.
Wait.
I want to make one more
modification to the character.
COMPUTER:
Specify.
Deny Kathryn Janeway
any future access
to his behavioral subroutines.
Modification complete.
Save program.
( computer beeps )