That's one planet
that never showed up
on the multiple choice exam.
TUVOK:
Its gravimetric readings
are similar
to that of a collapsed
dwarf star.
It also resembles a quasar
in that it has a high rate
of rotation--
approximately 58 revolutions
per minute.
Shall we take
a closer look?
That's what we're here for.
Tom, put us
in a high orbit.
Aye.
( console beeping )
Our warp drive
is off-line.
Why?
Unknown.
Back us off.
Our impulse engines
aren't responding.
Then use
the auxiliary thrusters.
We're in some kind
of gravimetric gradient.
It's pulling us
toward the planet.
The new one
is brighter than Tahal
or any of his brothers
in the sky.
What does he want from us?
SHAMAN:
To answer that,
we must learn
the nature of this god.
We must understand
the reason for his arrival.
You were making
an offering to Tahal.
I placed the fire-fruit
on his altar.
Then the ground shook.
I looked up...
and the new one was there.
The fire-fruit-- where is it?
The new one doesn't want Tahal
to have the fire-fruit.
Make an altar for him...
as big as Tahal's.
The fire-fruit
is only for the new one.
No more for the people!
It is his alone.
Ground Shaker...
Light Bringer...
take this today and every day!
Accept our offering!
Do not harm us.
Report.
We're in synchronous orbit,
57,000 kilometers
above the planet's equator.
Good work, Tom.
Now let's see...
You're patting the wrong guy
on the back.
Explain.
Our thrusters went off-line
halfway through our descent,
and then we just stopped,
like we were caught
in something.
I'm picking up a strong
tachyon field along the hull.
It could be
what's holding us.
Seven of Nine to the Bridge.
Go ahead, Seven.
Please report to Astrometrics.
There's something you must see.
On my way.
Chakotay.
SEVEN:
This planet has a tachyon core.
It's produced a subspace
particle field
which runs between the poles.
Voyager's arrival
disrupted that field.
It looks like
the ship's been caught
in an eddy of some kind.
It's worse than that.
Voyager seems
to have become
the planet's
third pole.
The imbalance is affecting
the outer crust.
I've picked up indications of
high-frequency seismic activity.
Caused by our presence?
Possibly.
Does anybody
live down there?
SEVEN:
The atmosphere is having
a scattering effect
on our sensors.
Is that vegetation?
According to sensors, yes.
The tachyon core has created
a space-time differential
between the planet
and the surrounding space.
We're watching the seasons
change in a matter of seconds.
For each second
that passes on Voyager,
nearly a day goes by
on the planet.
Scan for inhabitants.
I can't isolate
individual life-forms.
It'll take time to correct
for the space-time differential.
A couple of hundred
years, maybe?
If our orbit starts to decay,
Voyager will begin to feel
the effects of the differential,
and we'll begin aging
hundreds of times faster
than we would in normal space.
Unless we want to live our lives
in the blink of an eye,
I suggest we find
a way out of here.
How's our warp core?
The matter/antimatter reaction
is still active,
but this field we're stuck in
is raising hell
with the nacelles.
Until we break orbit,
warp drive is off-line.
And without warp drive,
we'll never leave orbit.
It does pose a bit
of a problem,
doesn't it?
Maybe the key is to learn
more about this planet,
in case we're
missing something.
The sensors aren't having
an easy time of it, either.
Then let's modify
a class-5 probe
for low orbit.
See what
we can pick up.
Configure the program
to scan along all subspace
bands, and set it
for visual images
every ten milliseconds.
Snapshots.
Why do I get the feeling
you're not just interested
in tachyon fields?
This could be the greatest
anthropological find
of my career.
If there's an intelligent
species down there,
we'll be able to track
their development--
not just for days or weeks,
but for centuries.
Watch them discover
new and better ways
of beating each other
over the head.
They won't necessarily
follow the Klingon model.
As opposed to the human model?
It'll take a few hours
to make the adjustments.
A few hours.
We might miss the rise
and fall of a civilization.
So we'll watch the next one.
( coughs )
Oh. Oh, Protector.
You're late.
Well, the hill
is steep, and I...
I'm not as young
as I used to be.
More heat.
Yes, Protector.
There are grave
matters of state here
that cannot be delayed.
Oh, Protector,
what exactly are you doing?
PROTECTOR:
I'm sending
him a letter.
Him?
S-S-Sending who a letter?
The Ground Shaker.
The Light Bringer.
Well, had you been
more attentive to my lessons
when you were a boy,
you would not be
so gullible as a man.
On the contrary--
you taught me well.
Our ignorant ancestors believed
every star was a deity.
You taught me
how foolish that was.
Superstition,
you called it.
And that's exactly what it is.
Hungry?
Well, it's, uh, bad fortune
to eat the fire-fruit.
According to whom?
Our ancestors?
Don't tell me you believe
that old superstition.
Perhaps we shouldn't
completely ignore
the old beliefs,
no matter how strange
they may seem today.
Ground Shaker...
Ground... Shaker.
Isn't it possible the name
was not given arbitrarily?
That this star
is indeed responsible
for knocking down our walls
and making us stumble
as we walk?
( chuckling ):
Oh, yes, I heard about that--
my condolences.
You heard what?
Well, that you stumbled
in front of several
important people
uh, d-d-during
the last ground shake.
Uh, very embarrassing, I'm sure.
I did nothing of the sort.
Well, my, uh...
uh, uh...
my hearing is not as good
as it used to be,
nor my memory, either.
Now, uh... uh,
what were we talking about?
We were talking
about ancient superstitions.
Now, I don't believe
for a moment
that the stars are gods,
but then, what are they?
A great mystery
to which there is no answer.
I believe the sky
is full of people
just like ourselves.
( gasps ):
Wha...?
( chuckling ):
Oh, nonsense.
Prove me wrong.
I say each star
encompasses a city,
and the Ground Shaker rules
one of these cities--
a fellow Protector.
If I'm correct, then
he'll listen to me,
one Protector to another.
Your pen.
I, Kelemane...
"Kelemane..."
son of Kelemane,
ruler of the good people
of the land below you,
demand that you stop
what you're...
"Demand"?
"Would hope"?
Ah, better. Much better.
...would hope that
you might consider
putting an end to whatever it
is you're doing
that shakes our ground.
If this causes
you inconvenience,
I'm willing
to offer a recompense.
"...a recom... pense."
I await your reply.
The next series of scans
is coming through.
I'm downloading them
into the display buffer.
No doubt about it.
There's a city down there.
Elevated levels of
carbon monoxide, ammonium--
that's progress, all right.
They've developed
internal combustion technology
since the last few scans.
Look at those radial lines.
It looks like
a system of roads.
Well, one thing hasn't changed.
The geological disturbances
that Voyager seems
to be causing.
The probe recorded
half a dozen each month.
Still no way to tell
how severe they are.
Look at the amount of iron
being used in that city.
That's ten times
what you'd expect to see
in a culture
at this stage of development.
Do you think they're using it
to support their buildings?
If you lived on a planet
that wouldn't stop shaking,
you might be doing
the same thing.
If they've reached this stage
of industrial development,
they must be observing us.
( console beeps )
The probe's impulse thrusters
are starting to fail.
At its present altitude,
it's been operating
for over 200 years.
Its orbit
is becoming decayed.
Initiate self-destruct.
It disintegrated
in the upper thermosphere.
If they saw anything, it just
looked like a shooting star.
Any response
to our transmission?
Nothing.
No visual change either.
Surprised?
Send it again.
The entire sequence?
How about
just the prime numbers?
You're tired.
So are you.
The prime numbers
and the elemental constants.
Then we'll stop.
An acceptable compromise.
It's not as if
they're going anywhere,
if they even exist
in the first place.
Do you doubt that?
I doubt everything.
So you weren't one
of those children
that had the entire series
of Sky Ship Friends, hmm?
Actually, I had them all,
even the duplicates.
You couldn't walk into my home
without tripping over
a friend or two.
Not in our home.
My grandfather
wouldn't allow it.
He told us that the Sky Ship
was a palace
where an evil Protector
lived.
He said that bad children
were sent there to be punished.
At this point,
I'd be happy to see anything...
evil or not.
Can you boost
the signal?
We're already at maximum.
Maybe if we
switched
to a different
carrier wave...
( rumbling )
If there is somebody up there,
they don't like us very much.
Any beings capable
of building that Sky Ship
could have destroyed
our world long ago.
They're not causing
the tremors on purpose.
What if they're all dead?
If you truly believe that,
why did you join this project?
Well, I doubt everything,
remember?
Even my own doubts.
I hope someone is up there.
So do I.
If they won't respond
to mathematics,
perhaps we should try
a more personal approach.
Here.
Say hello.
How could they possibly speak
our language?
There's only one way
to find out.
What... what
should I say?
Oh, "Glad
to meet you.
Where are you from?
Please stop
shaking our planet."
( console beeping )
An ultrahigh frequency signal
is being transmitted
from the surface.
The modulation
is unfamiliar.
Its Doppler
component is...
Any signal from the surface
will be accelerated.
When it reached
our time frame,
the frequency would be
thousands of times
higher than normal.
I'll attempt to
slow it down.
( high tones )
Again.
( lower tones sound )
Amplitude modulation.
It's a radio transmission.
( signal beeping )
It's a numerical
sequence.
Prime numbers.
They're sending
a list of prime numbers.
Followed by a sequence
of mathematical constants
and what appears
to be a vocal modulation.
Slow it down again.
( squeaking )
A little more.
Good friends in the Sky Ship--
I call you that,
hoping at least
you're not enemies.
There's nothing on our world
that resembles your technology,
so we assume you came here
from a nearby planet
or a distant star.
Our ancient mythology describes
your arrival centuries ago
coinciding with the tremors
that continually
shake our planet
and destroy so many
of our accomplishments.
I hope that was never
your intention.
But the result is the same.
Respond if you can,
or if you wish,
come down from your Sky Ship
and visit us.
Well, we've got to let them know
we're not doing it on purpose.
TUVOK:
Inadvisable.
The Prime Directive
still applies.
This transmission was made
with primitive radio technology.
They are not
a warp-capable civilization.
To hell with the
Prime Directive.
That man deserves an answer.
Don't forget
the temporal differential.
That man has been dead
for a long time.
Nearly a century by now.
Okay, so we send a message
to his great-grandchildren.
I'll gladly do the honors.
Ancient mythology--
that means we've already
insinuated ourselves
into their culture.
Why not take the next step?
First contact
with the pre-warp society.
We've already made
first contact.
They know we're up here.
They've known
for hundreds of years,
which means our presence
has been tempered by time.
We've gradually become
part of their mythos.
Meeting us could
throw that belief
system into chaos.
But we're destroying
their planet.
You heard him.
A first contact, face-to-face,
might give us information
we could use to leave orbit.
That would stop the damage.
It's worth the risk.
We don't even know
if an away team
could survive the transition
to their time frame.
Doctor, correct me if I'm wrong,
but the physiological stress
could be fatal.
For one of you, perhaps,
but not for me.
My holo-matrix
would be unaffected.
You'd be going
only as an observer.
You're not to
make contact.
I localized the source
of the transmission
to a subcontinent
in the southern
hemisphere.
The Central Protectorate.
How do you know that?
I've been looking at the data
from Astrometrics.
Seven's picked up a few
of their local transmissions.
I can tell you the names
of all 26 states on the planet.
And all the best places to eat?
Just about.
So, is this Central
Protectorate
a good place to
send the Doctor?
Probably. Judging
from the transmissions,
they seem to have
a tolerant society.
Hmm. Well, just to
be on the safe side,
I'll find him
an isolated spot.
I'm giving you access
to your facial
and epidermal parameters.
You should be able
to mimic the appearance
of whoever is down there
in a matter of seconds.
What if they're big
purple blobs of protoplasm?
Then you'll be the best-looking
blob on the planet.
I'm keeping you down there
for three seconds, Doctor.
That'll be almost two days
in their time frame.
Gather whatever data you can--
seismic charts,
meteorological records,
anything that might give us
a clue about how to break orbit.
Understood.
This will speed up
the scanning rate
of your program...
allow you to make
the transition.
( sighs )
See you soon.
Energizing.
One...
two...
three.
The confinement beam
is destabilizing.
It's the temporal field.
We'll have to recalibrate.
Every second he's down
there, he's in danger
of being discovered.
Locking on again.
We've lost him.
I'm scanning within
a 100-kilometer radius
of where we sent
him-- nothing.
He could've moved
across the continent by now
or to the other side
of the planet.
Increasing radius
to 1,000 kilometers.
Chakotay to Seven of Nine.
SEVEN:
Go ahead, Commander.
Have you picked up
any information
regarding opera houses
or concert halls?
The cultural center
of the state runs
along the shore
of the eastern lake.
Got him.
B'Elanna, stand by
for the coordinates.
Acknowledged.
I've reinitialized
the confinement beam.
It's holding.
Locking on.
Captain!
Lieutenant!
( grunts )
I thought I'd never
see you again.
Are you all right?
Oh, I-I've had
a few close calls
over the years,
but all in all...
"Years"?
It's been over three.
But at least I knew you
hadn't left me behind.
All I had to do was look
up, and there you were,
the brightest
star in the sky.
Well, what do they
know about us?
Only that we arrived here
centuries ago.
They blame us for
the seismic tremors,
but everything else
is pure speculation.
And let me tell you,
they like nothing better
than to speculate
about Voyager.
( chuckles ):
Doric would go
on and on--
"Sky Ship this,
Sky Ship that."
Doric?
The owner of the
building I lived in,
until the war started.
There was a war?
Oh... the neighboring
state decided
to lob a few cannon
shells at us.
Our tactical air
command responded,
and a new treaty
was signed...
in a matter of weeks,
but not before my
apartment was in ruins.
Oh, so they have
aviation technology?
They're hardly
savages, Captain.
In fact, they're
making great strides
technologically,
thanks, in part,
to Voyager.
What do you mean?
From the moment our ship
arrived in the sky,
they've been trying
to make contact.
Our presence...
has encouraged invention,
religion,
science, art,
even children's toys.
They're all variations
on a single theme--
Voyager.
Mariza even composed an aria
based on
the Sky Ship.
I sang the lyric.
Mariza?
She was my...
roommate.
( sighs )
Three years is a long time,
Captain.
One needs...
companionship.
You'll get no argument from me.
But did you learn anything
that might help
us break orbit?
It's all in here.
( sighs )
Meteorological
records
for the last 300 years--
I've committed them all
to memory.
Some are
inaccurate almanacs,
but the more
recent ones include
detailed seismic analyses.
Get that information
to Astrometrics.
See if you can find any
pattern to the quakes.
Might help us figure
a way out of here.
See you in Sick Bay.
I'll download the data
from your program,
and we'll do
a little cosmetic surgery, too.
Lieutenant?
Unless you prefer
looking like that.
Of course-- I completely forgot.
( chuckles )
I must tell you,
if some of the people
on the planet had their way,
those weapons would
be pointed at Voyager.
Luckily, the ship is still
out of range-- for now.
I guess I can't
blame them.
There's something
of a space race going on
between the various states.
Who can get to the starship
first with a rocket?
Are we talking about a
capsule with an astronaut
or a missile
with a warhead?
I can't answer that.
But at their present rate
of development,
we won't have to wait
very long to find out.
How does this sound?
"The Weird Planet
Where Time Moved Very Fast
and So Did the People
Who Lived There,"
by Naomi Wildman.
That's what I'm calling my
report for astronomy class.
Neelix said I should choose
a planet to write about.
So I picked this one.
Your title is...
verbose.
I suggest you try
to condense it.
"The Weird Planet."
Better,
but it lacks precision.
"The Weird Planet
Displaced in Time."
Perfect.
Seven of Nine to the Bridge.
I'm transmitting my calculations
directly to the helm.
JANEWAY:
Acknowledged.
What's happening?
The Doctor brought back data
regarding the planet's
graviton field.
We're using it
to realign our thrusters.
That'll be great for my report.
All hands, this is the Captain.
Secure your stations
and prepare to break orbit.
Brace yourself.
Our altitude
is increasing.
50 meters...
60...
( alarm bleeping )
Seven of Nine
to the Bridge.
Our attempt
to leave orbit
is increasing
the seismic activity.
We must abort.
JANEWAY:
Agreed.
Is the planet okay?
Minimal damage along
the equatorial coastline--
nothing serious.
Seven... do you think
we'll ever be able to leave?
Eventually.
I hope so.
I need a way to end my report.
Orbital 1
to Launch Control.
We're ready to ignite
second-stage propellants.
LAUNCH CONTROL:
Proceed.
Second-stage propellants
depleted.
Final stage-- ready.
Ready to ignite
final-stage propellants.
Launch Control,
we are awaiting
your command to proceed.
( squeaking )
What was that?
There's nothing wrong
with the transponder.
Orbital 1
to Launch Control.
We're not receiving
your orders.
Everything else
is working perfectly.
Ignite the final stage.
We have to proceed
with the mission.
Final-stage propellants
depleted.
Initiate deceleration thrusters.
( pushing buttons )
Thrusters active.
Watch your pitch angle.
Correcting.
Distance check.
We're in rendezvous range.
Rendezvous sequence...
locked in.
Moving into final position.
Distance check.
We're within scanning range.
Let's take a look.
( beeping )
The scans won't penetrate
their hull.
I guess we'll
have to go inside.
We're not authorized to do that.
Our orders were to learn
as much as possible
about the Sky Ship.
That's my intention.
I saw something
that looks like
a transfer port.
It might be a
place we can dock.
Move in closer.
Wait, wait.
Are you all right?
A little...
disoriented.
Let's keep going.
I don't understand.
Her skin feels warm.
It might be some sort
of metabolic stasis...
but then,
why does it look like
they're just going
about their business?
( sighs ):
This isn't right.
We shouldn't be here.
We were never
meant to be here.
Try and stay calm.
We've seen enough.
Please, we
have to leave.
You're the best pilot
we have.
That's why you're
on this mission.
This is no different
than flying your favorite...
Oh, it's different.
I can't argue with that.
Another few minutes,
then we'll go back.
This looks like
their command center.
This is not
metabolic stasis.
Could the laws of physics
be different here?
Maybe they're just
a little slower.
( gasps and groans )
What's wrong?
( groaning )
( both gasping and groaning )
Intruder alert.
Security Team to Deck 1.
Captain, I'm picking up a ship
at Docking Port 1.
It just appeared there.
Bridge to Sick Bay.
Medical emergency.
What can you tell me?
The transition
to our time frame
was a little
rough for them.
I'm afraid his colleague
didn't make it.
How is he?
Recovering.
Lucky for him, I'm as good
as his family doctor.
After three years
of poring over their
medical journals,
I know as much about their
physiology as I do yours.
Easy.
Where's Terina?
She didn't survive
the transition.
I'm very sorry.
Transition?
To your time frame?
You understand
what's happened to you.
I'm beginning to.
Voyager exists
in the same space-time
as the rest of the galaxy.
Your planet is different.
So you really haven't been
watching us for centuries.
Actually, we just got here...
and we're hoping you can help us
find a way to leave.
So, if what you're
saying is true,
everyone I know...
everyone I knew is gone.
That's correct.
Captain, I'm an
accomplished pilot.
That's why they chose me
for this mission.
I don't have the courage
of the others.
They made a mistake
choosing me.
I have to disagree.
For someone whose
life has just been
turned upside down, I
think you're doing fine.
When I was a young child,
the toys hanging above my crib
depicted the Sky Ship.
It's the first thing
I ever remember seeing,
even before my mother's face...
and now I'm the only one
that knows its name--
Voyager.
I suppose it'll be
the last thing I see as well.
Well, that's up to you.
I have no intention
of keeping you here
against your will.
The Doctor spent some
time on your planet
collecting data that
we hoped would help us
find a way to leave orbit.
We need you
to assist us
in interpreting
that information.
However...
the longer you stay on board,
the more difficult it will be
for you to go home.
Your culture
is changing
every second
you're here.
By the time you go back,
you might find it
more alien than ours.
♪ Star of the night,
star of the day ♪
♪ Come to take
my tears away ♪
♪ Make my life
always bright... ♪
It's a child's prayer.
To Voyager?
Yes.
I hope you're not disappointed.
How often does your
very first dream come true?
Of course I'll help you.
The information I brought back
is in Voyager's database.
Seven of Nine has been trying
to make sense of it.
She'll welcome
your assistance.
Mountain or Lakeside?
Mountain, of course.
Don't tell me you're
a Lakeside supporter.
You really were
on the surface.
How are they doing
this season?
Not good-- five
wins, 12 losses.
I don't believe it.
Who's guarding for them?
Torelius.
Any relation
to the Torelius?
His grandson.
I saw the original
defend for Mountain
in the playoffs
against Red River.
That was before
I was born.
He would have gone
into voluntary exile
after a 5-12 season!
This information
is out of date.
We were far more advanced
than this when I left.
I can help you correct it.
Very well.
Let's start
with the geological data.
The seismic detectors back then
were off by a variance of 3.8.
A simple conversion will
compensate for that.
Does every planet
look like ours?
None that I've seen.
Your world appears to be unique.
If we're so out of step
with everything else,
we'll never be able to explore
space the way you have.
You're a highly
adaptable species.
Your scientists will find a way
to compensate
for the temporal differential.
They'd better do it
before you leave.
Without the Sky Ship
up above them,
my people might lose interest
in progress.
There wouldn't be anything left
to reach for.
Perhaps they'll
miss Voyager so much,
they'll do everything they can
to follow us.
Maybe so.
( console beeping )
What was that?
An antimatter implosion.
Your world is experimenting
with warp technology.
Sensors detected
an early test.
( beeping )
Another test--
six weeks later.
( beeping )
And a third-- more
controlled each time.
They're learning quickly.
( explosion )
Too quickly.
What was that?
Unknown, but our shields
are down to 82 percent.
( explosion )
64 percent.
I don't know what's causing it.
There's nothing on sensors.
Janeway to Seven of Nine.
Go ahead, Captain.
Are you picking up anything
in Astrometrics?
The inhabitants
appear to have
developed antimatter
torpedo technology.
I believe we're under attack.
TUVOK:
Another direct hit.
Shields at 49 percent.
Captain, I apologize
for this attack.
They have no right.
Unfortunately,
they've got every right.
Let me talk to them.
We've already tried
to hail them. It doesn't
look like they're able
to receive
our transmissions.
They still don't know
about the time differential.
A logical assumption.
Shields down
to 34 percent.
The torpedoes are being fired
at three-day intervals.
They're making
refinements each time,
increasing the detonation yield.
Captain, isn't it time
we returned fire?
We've done enough damage
to these people over
the last thousand years.
You've got to go back.
It's the only way.
Make them understand who we are.
You have the specifications
of this ship.
Your scientists might be able
to use them to help free us.
At the very least,
get them to hold their fire.
KIM:
Captain, the transporters
are off-line.
Is his vessel still intact?
The docking port
hasn't been hit yet.
Good luck.
This will accelerate your
metabolic functions--
help you make
the transition.
Thank you
for everything, Doctor.
It was a pleasure to
treat a fellow citizen.
Would you
do me a favor?
Certainly.
Find out what
happened to a boy
named Jason Tabreez.
He lived in the
Central Protectorate.
Jason? An unusual name.
Yes. He was my...
son.
But you're a hologram.
It's a long story.
He's dead by now,
but perhaps you could
discover what happened to him.
Maybe he had children
or grandchildren.
You could tell them about me.
I will.
Orbital 1 to Launch Control.
Please respond.
Launch Control, please respond.
FEMALE ( over radio ):
Who is this?
Pilot First Rank Gotana-Retz.
Clear this channel,
or I'm going to report you
to the Command Center.
Is this Launch Control?
I'm the Weather Coordinator
for Station 004.
You're in violation
of transmission regulations.
Please, listen to me.
I'm trying
to reach Launch Control.
Let me guess. You finally
decided to come home.
You're Gotana-Retz?
Gotana-Retz. Yes.
Now, please transfer me
to Launch Control.
Launch Control became
the Tactical Command Center
50 years ago.
You're dead.
I've been inside the Sky Ship.
Then it's a good thing
you decided to leave.
They're about to shoot it down.
I've got to speak with them!
Tactical Command frequencies
are classified.
Now, get off this channel.
If you've ever wanted
to report more than the weather,
now is your chance.
Tell them to clear Central Lake
of all traffic.
Orbital 1 is coming in
for a landing.
Shields at 23 percent.
17 percent.
Shields are down.
What was that last one?
A tricobalt
device.
What'll they think of next?
Damage reports coming in--
imminent hull breaches
on Decks 8, 9 and 10.
Life support
is failing.
Our astronaut should
have made it by now.
KIM:
Based on his descent velocity,
he landed about ten minutes ago.
That's a year
and a half.
Then he must have failed.
I'm picking up
another launch--
two massive
energy signatures.
Tricobalt devices?
Unknown.
Brace yourselves.
We're in some kind
of tractor beam.
PARIS:
Captain...
if I alternate thrusters,
I might be able
to break us free.
No. Let's give our friends
the benefit of the doubt.
They're pulling us away
from the planet.
We've broken orbit.
Try hailing them.
It's good to see you all again.
Looks like somebody down there
listened to you.
I'm sorry it took so long.
And now we can make first
contact the proper way.
Unfortunately,
that won't be possible.
A temporal compensator.
It allows me to exist
in your time frame
without actually leaving my own,
but, uh, only for a few minutes.
I'm afraid it'll be a while
before my people
actually join
the rest of the galaxy.
TUVOK:
Captain, we'll
be able to bring
the warp drive back on line
in approximately two hours.
Very good.
Thank you.
I feel like
I'm saying good-bye
to an old friend.