Captain's Log,
Stardate 53556.4.
We've towed
a damaged vessel aboard
and are attempting to repair it
while the Doctor treats
the Qomarian crew
who have suffered
minor injuries.
Stay away.
If you don't cooperate,
I can't treat you.
When we agreed
to be examined
by this ship's
Medical Officer,
we didn't know
that you were
a primitive
computer matrix.
I assure you there is
nothing primitive about me.
Hmm.
I am programmed
to perform
more than five million
medical procedures.
Does that include
bloodletting?
No, but I'll be happy to
add it to my repertoire.
( over-articulating ):
We are ready to
return to our ship.
Could you contact one
of your superiors?
Doctor to the Captain.
Please report to Sick Bay.
JANEWAY:
Already on my way.
( over-articulating ):
The Captain is
coming here now.
If you want to talk to her,
you can have a seat.
It is a very
irritating program.
Maybe we can disable
its speech subroutines.
You're not
authorized
to do that.
How are our
guests?
( sighs )
Their injuries
are minor.
Unfortunately, I
can't say the same
for their lack
of manners.
Doctor.
What is the status
of our ship?
To be honest, we're having
a little trouble
understanding
your technology.
The problem is
Interference from your
antiquated scanning devices
shut down
our propulsion system.
FEMALE:
Forgive us, Captain.
We live
in a closed system.
We are not accustomed
to interacting
with other species,
especially inferior ones.
Well, then...
I guess we'll leave the repairs
in your superior hands.
Our injuries will have
to be treated first.
Is there someone other
than this hologram
who could help us?
No one who's better qualified.
Hmm.
Very well.
Try to bear
with our deficiencies
just a little longer.
( sighs )
This way, please.
( humming "I've Been Working
on the Railroad" )
♪ I've been working
on the railroad ♪
♪ All the livelong day ♪
♪ I've been working
on the railroad ♪
♪ Just to pass
the time away... ♪
MALE:
What is that?
This? A hypospray.
No.
What you were doing.
Preparing your
medication.
No. With your voice.
You mean... singing?
"Singing".
Do it again.
Yes, do it again.
♪ Someone's in the kitchen
with Dinah ♪
I know-ow-ow-ow ♪
♪ Someone's in the kitchen
with Dinah ♪
♪ Strummin' on the old banjo
and singin' ♪
♪ Fee, fi, fiddle-ee-i-o ♪
♪ Fee, fi,
fiddle-ee-i-o-o-o-o ♪
♪ Fee, fi, fiddle-ee-i-o... ♪
♪ Strummin' on the old banjo. ♪
It is a unique
mathematical variation.
Difficult to quantify.
How do you suppose
the algorithms are generated?
Maybe it's a fractal.
Or wave-form calculus.
Do you mean to say a culture
as superior as yours
has never heard music
of any kind?
There are other
kinds of music?
Of course.
The little ditty I just sang
is an early American folk song,
but countless cultures
have produced
thousands
of types of...
music--
instrumental,
choral, orchestral.
What is the purpose
of this "music"?
Is it an encryption
code of some kind?
There is a mathematical
component to music,
but primarily it's a form
of artistic expression.
"Artistic expression"?
Using sounds
and images
to convey ideas
and emotions.
Why would
anyone do that?
Well... to... communicate
their feelings.
Can't they do that
through speech?
Yes, but music
is much more...
expressive and
entertaining.
You mean to say
that this "music" is...
recreational?
( sighs )
It does have
other applications.
Uh, as a matter of fact,
I've recently been doing
some research into
its therapeutic properties,
but... yes, primarily,
we use it for...
enjoyment.
"We"?
You mean to say
others aboard your ship
are capable
of producing this phenomenon?
Well, maybe not
with my level of expertise,
but there are
quite a few members of this crew
who possess
musical skills.
Maybe we judged this
culture too quickly.
Hmm.
Our database contains
the works
of thousands
of musicians and composers.
If you'd like, I could download
some selections for you.
Could you sing
them for us?
Captain's Log, supplemental.
The Qomar have completed
repairs to their ship
and, surprisingly,
have invited us
to visit their system.
Apparently, it's no longer
"closed" to outsiders.
Harry, can you make sense
of any of this?
We're picking up thousands
of subspace transmissions,
all encrypted differently.
Between the satellites
and the spacecraft,
it's like navigating
an obstacle course.
With all this traffic,
the Qomar might not
even know we're here.
Apparently, they do.
We are being hailed.
FEMALE:
Captain, you now have
the privilege
of meeting Prelate Koru.
Welcome to the Qomar
Planetary Alliance.
Thank you, Prelate.
We're looking forward
to learning more
about your culture.
Our civilization is
no doubt intimidating.
We'll do what we can
to avoid overwhelming
you during your stay.
I appreciate that.
I understand
we're not as advanced as you,
but we're fast learners,
and we'd like to...
We want to learn more
about the algorithmic
expressions
you call "music".
We're prepared
to give you complete access
to our musical database,
as well as...
Your Emergency
Medical Hologram.
We'd consider an
exchange of technology
if you give us complete
access to this device.
I believe he's made
some recordings.
No, not recordings.
How about a recital?
"Recital"?
A live performance.
We can put
together a program
of various
styles of music.
Uh, will the Emergency
Medical Hologram sing?
He'll be the
star attraction.
( singing aria from
Don Carlos )
Thank you.
You're very kind.
That was a selection
from the opera Don Carlos,
composed by Giuseppe Verdi,
a towering figure
in Earth's musical history.
Another human musical form
is called "jazz",
which has flourished
since the early 20th century.
Mathematically, you'll find
the rhythmic structures
quite interesting, particularly
the use of syncopation,
which is said
to make the music swing.
( laughter and chatter )
You may also notice
some fascinating
trigonometric functions
in the counterpoint,
but I suppose I'm going off
on a tangent, aren't I?
( laughter )
So, without further ado,
I give you Harry Kim
and the Kimtones.
( slow jazz intro playing )
( "That Old Black Magic"
playing  )
( whispering )
We wish to hear
the Doctor.
FEMALE:
Yes, the Doctor.
MALE:
Bring back
the Doctor.
FEMALE:
We want the
Doctor to sing.
Doc, they're dying
up there.
You've got
to do something.
Pick up the tempo.
( upbeat tempo plays )
♪ That old black magic has me
in its spell ♪
♪ That old black magic
that you weave so well ♪
♪ Those icy fingers
up and down my spine ♪
♪ The same old witchcraft
when your eyes meet mine ♪
♪ The same old tingle
that I feel inside ♪
♪ And then,
that elevator starts its ride ♪
♪ And down and down I go ♪
♪ 'Round and 'round I go ♪
♪ Like a leaf
that's caught in the tide... ♪
Well, if you like jazz,
you're going to love
rock 'n' roll.
It was one of the 20th century's
greatest inventions.
Does the Doctor sing
rock 'n' roll?
I wouldn't say it's
his favorite genre.
No, he's more
of an opera man.
As am I.
( buzz of conversation )
Aren't you one
of the musicians?
Harry Kim.
Vinka.
Welcome aboard
Voyager.
Um, if you'd like to see
the rest of the ship,
I'd be happy to
give you a tour.
Maybe later.
I was wondering if you could
introduce me to the Doctor.
( sighs )
Congratulations, Doctor,
you stole the show.
Thank you, Captain,
but I can't take all the credit.
There was something in the air,
a certain magic.
It was one of those
rare moments
when audience and performer
become one.
Doctor.
Prelate. Tincoo.
I will introduce your singing
to more of our people.
I'm flattered.
You will perform
on our planet.
I'd consider
it an honor,
but you'll have to negotiate
the terms
with my... representative.
I don't understand.
I believe the Doctor
is referring to me, Prelate.
Another concert would mean
extending our stay.
When would you want
to schedule the performance?
As soon as possible.
The Doctor could perform
at one of the lecture halls
at the university.
I'm not sure a lecture hall
would meet
the acoustic requirements.
TINCOO:
I'll help you make
whatever modifications
you think are necessary.
Sounds like you've
got yourself a
booking, Doctor.
DOCTOR:
I'd like to reproduce a backdrop
which was used in
a production of Pagliacci
at Teatro de la Scala--
Earth's most famous
opera house.
It's beautiful.
Your taste in design
is as refined
as your taste in music.
We'll replicate
it for you.
Excellent,
but we still have the problem
with the sight lines.
What's wrong
with the sight lines?
If you consider the height
of the average Qomar,
it's obvious that anyone
seated in the back five rows
will have an obstructed view.
You're right.
They won't be able
to see anything
but the top of your head.
The glare could blind them.
You'll have to excuse
Lieutenant Torres.
Her appreciation
of music is limited
to a smattering
of Klingon drinking songs.
We'll have to increase
the rake of the floor
by five degrees.
You really think
they're going to redesign
an entire building just
to appeal to your vanity?
Vanity has nothing
to do with it, Lieutenant.
I'm concerned
about my audience.
We are prepared to make
whatever changes
the Doctor thinks
are necessary.
DOCTOR:
Thank you, Tincoo.
While we're at it,
Lieutenant,
I'll need some help
with my wardrobe.
I'm an Engineer,
not a costume designer.
I'd like you to make
an adjustment
to my mobile emitter
that would allow me
to make quick changes
between songs.
That sounds exciting.
Oh, it will be.
I plan to segue from
Don Juan to Rigoletto
in the blink of an eye.
It will be a triumph of...
Arrogance
and self-absorption?
Just trying to help.
Your crewmates don't seem
to appreciate your abilities.
You've noticed that, too.
That must be very
frustrating for you.
You have no idea.
( whispering ):
We'll be starting
in two minutes.
I'd better get
into costume.
How do I look?
You look perfect.
I wish I had a subroutine
to eliminate pre-show jitters.
I could help you
add one to your program.
You're very sweet.
I'm just a little...
nervous.
Why?
I'm about to expose your
entire culture to music
for the first time.
The responsibility
is... enormous.
Your performance tonight
will be transmitted
to hundreds of millions
of people.
Is that supposed
to help me relax?
It's time.
( light applause )
( loud applause )
( alarm sounding )
Report.
I didn't order a
Red Alert, Captain.
Well, someone did.
The command
originated in...
Astrometrics.
Seven of Nine to the Captain.
I've found evidence
that the Qomar are attempting
to sabotage Voyager.
On my way.
JANEWAY:
What have you got?
I believe the Qomar
are attempting to disable
our com system.
How?
By overloading it
with millions
of teraquads of
irrelevant data.
What do you mean
by "irrelevant"?
They're transmissions...
all addressed to the Doctor.
Precisely.
I've only been able
to decipher
a small fraction
of them so far,
but they include invitations
to social
and scientific functions,
requests
for personal encounters,
and cloying tributes
to the Doctor's talents.
Computer, stand
down Red Alert.
This isn't
sabotage, Seven.
This is fan mail.
Fan mail?
People who admire
performers
are called "fans".
The word, I believe,
derives from "fanatic".
Exactly.
Why would the Doctor inspire
fanaticism among the Qomar?
Music is new to them.
Clearly, they're
very excited about it.
This glorification
of the individual
is irrational.
The Doctor is merely reproducing
the work of others.
Why do his fans fixate
solely on him?
I suppose he's
the embodiment of
what they admire.
He can do something
they can't,
and that makes
him special.
Perhaps, but that doesn't
explain their interest
in the minutiae
of the Doctor's life.
"What does he do
in his spare time?"
"To how many decimal places
can he calculate pi?"
This one wants to know his
favorite quadratic equation.
People have
always fantasized
about knowing
celebrities personally.
I suppose it's a way of making
themselves feel more important.
Tuvok to Janeway.
Go ahead.
We have a security problem
on Deck 2.
On my way.
Just think, Seven.
As personal friends
of the Doctor,
we're the envy of
millions of Qomar.
( sighs )
Our efforts to
accommodate them
have gotten out of hand.
I guess their interest
in the Doctor
is greater
than we expected.
( excited chatter and laughter)
Much greater.
I recommend we refuse
all further requests
for transport
from the surface.
Agreed.
And we should evacuate
these visitors
immediately.
They are interfering with
normal ship's functions.
Tuvok, when have functions
aboard this ship
ever been normal?
( Doctor singing
Italian opera)
( singing in harmony )
Thank you for coming.
Please accept this
eight-by-ten-by-four
singing replica of me.
One at a time,
one at a time, now.
Please, now, do not touch
the Doctor's mobile emitter.
Captain.
Isn't this exciting?
I'm not sure that's
the word I'd use for it.
Excuse me.
Sorry, excuse me.
I'm sorry, Captain,
but you'll have
to wait your turn
like everybody else.
I'm not here
for an autograph.
We need to talk.
I'm glad you're enjoying
yourself, Doctor,
but this is getting
a little excessive.
I'm only doing what
I can to ensure
that first contact with
the Qomar goes smoothly.
Does that include using
our replicator reserves
to create miniaturized
versions of yourself?
I would never
do such a thing.
As a matter of fact,
the Qomar have devoted
an entire holo
processing plant
to manufacturing
them for me.
I see.
Well, in any case,
you've been neglecting
your Sick Bay duties.
I haven't received
a report in three days.
Oh, come now, Kathryn.
It's not as though
there's been a flood
of medical emergencies.
I wasn't aware we were
on a first name basis.
I-I meant "Captain".
I'm sorry.
Oh, that's perfectly
all right, Doctor,
or do you prefer "Maestro"?
( chuckles ):
Please.
Either is acceptable.
Well, then, let me make
it clear to both of you:
Maestro, you're finished
for today.
Doctor, report
to Sick Bay, now.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't
the wandering minstrel.
What's the nature of their
medical emergencies?
Apparently,
these two young ladies
became dizzy and disoriented
while waiting in line
to see you.
I'll take over
from here.
Be careful, Doc.
You seem to be hazardous
to the Qomars' health.
I'm Vinka.
I'm Azen.
Hmm. Neither of you
appears to be ill.
We wanted to meet you
in a more intimate setting.
So we told your security
officer we were sick.
Sick Bay is for medical
treatment only.
I'm afraid you'll
have to leave.
But there's so much
about you we want to know.
Yes, you're a very
stimulating hologram.
I-if you're here for a replica,
they're available
in the Mess Hall.
We don't want a replica.
We want
the full-sized version.
I-I-I'm flattered,
really, but if you
don't leave now,
I'll have to call Security.
I'll bet you can calculate pi
to over a thousand digits.
Security to Sick Bay.
Have you ever balanced
simultaneous equations?
Computer, deactivate
Emergency Medical Hologram.
Here you are.
I needed to find
some peace and quiet.
I want to show
you something.
What's this?
You inspired me
to create
my own musical
composition.
It's based on
the intersection
of two fractals.
Tincoo, this is extraordinary.
I created it for you.
I don't know what to say.
Will you sing it?
I'm not sure I can.
It's very complex.
( singing )
( singing high notes )
The melody's lovely,
but some of these notes
are well beyond
the human vocal range.
You are not human.
No, but...
I can help you reconfigure
your vocal processors.
I don't think there's time.
My last concert's tomorrow.
Why does it have to be
your last concert?
Because Voyager is
scheduled to depart.
Stay here with us.
I have responsibilities
on Voyager.
They're a resourceful crew.
I am certain they
will find a way
to compensate
for your absence.
I'm not so sure about that...
but even if they could...
Voyager's the only
life I've ever known.
The crew are my friends.
But they don't appreciate you
the way we do--
you know that.
You could have a new
life here as a performer,
surrounded by people
who admire and respect
your talent.
It's very tempting, but...
By any mathematical standard,
the medical care of 150 people
cannot compare to the cultural
enrichment of millions.
You can't always explain things
with an equation, Tincoo.
What about the simplest equation
of them all?
One plus one.
I don't understand.
The time you have been here
has been the most stimulating
of my life.
I feel the same way
about my time with you.
Then stay here...
with me.
You're resigning
your commission?
I've been asked to stay.
When this all started,
I thought you might have
a little harmless fun,
and that
you'd be responsible enough
to keep it in perspective.
I can see now
that I was mistaken.
This isn't "harmless fun"
for me, Captain.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity to realize a dream.
What about your duty
to Voyager?
I take that
very seriously, but...
You're a part of this ship.
You sound as if you're talking
about a piece of equipment.
That's not what I meant.
Then shouldn't I be
given the same respect
as any flesh and blood
member of this crew?
Every member of this crew
is expected to fulfill
his obligations.
If Harry Kim met an alien woman
on an away mission,
fell in love and decided
to spend the rest
of his life with her,
raise a family, instead
of continuing on this journey,
you wouldn't stand in his way.
You're not Harry Kim.
You're an Emergency
Medical Hologram.
Then you do see me
as a piece of technology.
I have given you
extraordinary freedom--
to explore your creativity,
to go on away missions,
to pursue personal
relationships--
but enough is enough.
Why?!
Because you don't
see me as an equal,
and you never have. Admit it.
I am responsible
for the medical needs
of this crew.
If I let you leave,
what kind of Captain would I be?
Every other Starfleet officer
chose to be here,
but I never had a choice--
until now.
I've given this crew everything
for five years.
Isn't it worth anything?
Haven't I earned the right
to self-determination?
You've lost other systems before
and always managed
to find a solution.
You'll manage without me.
What about you?
Will you manage without us?
The Qomar are a technologically
advanced species.
I have no doubt that
my maintenance requirements
will be met.
Now which one of us
is looking at you as
a piece of technology?
I'm not talking about
your maintenance needs.
I'm talking about
your emotional needs.
You've got people on this
ship who care about you.
The Qomar certainly seem
to care about me.
And when their tastes change?
What makes you think
that's going to happen?
Fame is often temporary.
This isn't just about fame.
Oh, really?
If you must know...
there's a woman involved,
one who appreciates me in a way
no one on this crew ever has.
Well, it sounds like
you'll have everything you need.
I believe I will.
I hope so, Doctor,
because once Voyager's gone,
you won't be able
to change your mind.
That's a risk
I'm willing to take.
As your Captain,
I should refuse
this resignation,
but as your friend,
it wouldn't be right
to stand in your way.
And you can't let the
Captain ignore her health.
She's notorious for
finding any excuse
to miss her appointments.
I'll send her
weekly reminders.
And when Mr. Neelix
becomes convinced
that he's suffering
from the Toluncan Ague--
which he does
every flu season--
don't argue with him,
just give him a placebo.
Doc, I've been assisting
you for three years.
I know the drill.
Yes, I suppose you do.
Remember, I'll be within
com range for at least
another month,
so if any problems
should arise...
Doc...
you're not really going
to do this, are you?
I would have thought
you of all people
would be glad to see me go.
Are you kidding?
Who am I going to torment
after you're gone?
Well...
I've got some more good-byes.
I'll check in with you
before I leave.
I'll be here...
redecorating your office.
Hello, Seven.
I wanted to see
you before I left.
I've downloaded
some social lessons
we haven't
covered yet.
There are 17
new chapters.
Does one of them
include instructions
for ending a friendship?
Our friendship's
not over, Seven.
It will be difficult to maintain
if we never see
each other again.
I know it'll be hard
for you when I'm gone.
I will adapt.
Yes, I suppose
you will,
but it'll be
hard for me.
Why? You're getting everything
you've ever wanted.
I thought you'd
be the first one
to understand my desire
to grow as an individual.
What I don't understand
is why you can't do that
aboard Voyager.
I feel I've accomplished
all I can here.
Oh, there's the occasional
medical mystery
that challenges
my programming,
but mostly it's
become routine,
and frankly,
I feel my talents
are often taken
for granted.
But when I'm standing
on that stage performing,
and I see those rapt
faces in the audience...
I feel I finally
know what it's like
to be made of
flesh and blood.
You simply crave attention,
applause,
fan mail.
What if I do?
Those things
are irrelevant.
To you, maybe,
but to me, it makes me
feel appreciated,
even loved...
Not for what
I've been programmed to do,
but for who I've become.
KIM:
Doctor, you're receiving
a transmission.
Route it to Cargo Bay 2.
Doctor, this is Tincoo.
I want to see you immediately.
I have something to show you.
What is it?
A surprise.
I think you'll be very pleased.
I'll beam down
as soon as I can.
Seven...
You shouldn't keep
your fans waiting.
Thank you
for being so prompt.
Of course.
What's the surprise?
I had an inspiration.
Another musical
composition?
Better.
What's this?
I've solved
all our problems.
I wasn't aware
that we had any.
Well, you were reluctant
to leave your ship,
and you also doubted
your ability
to sing my composition,
so I created
a superior holo-matrix.
I-I don't understand.
It's simple.
Now you can
stay aboard Voyager,
and  he  can
sing for us.
Listen.
( singing )
( singing extremely
high notes)
( singing loud,
sustained high note )
You can't make
a superior singer
simply by creating
a new matrix.
I beg to differ.
My vocal processors
are enhanced
with polyphonic sequencers.
I am not only capable
of singing notes
well beyond your limited range,
I can produce
multiharmonic overtones
through the use
of amplitude vacillat...
Why did you do that?
Tincoo, music is more
than mathematics,
and I am much more
than a program
with musical subroutines.
All of my experience,
all of my passion
goes into every note
that I sing.
When you listen to me,
when my singing moves you,
you're not just hearing notes.
You're hearing my artistry...
my... soul.
I've duplicated that, too.
I thought you wanted me.
I did,
but now, I've developed
a far more sophisticated
piece of technology.
Technology...
I thought you would be pleased.
You seemed reluctant
to leave your ship.
You told me that the time
you had spent with me
was the most stimulating
of your life.
It was. You inspired me
to do my greatest work.
But I thought...
Yes?
That you and I...
What?
Well, I suppose I'm no longer
on the bill tomorrow.
Of course you are.
It will be
your farewell performance.
Of course.
( singing strained high note)
You wanted to see me?
I need your clearance code
to delete my medical database.
You sure you want
to do that?
If you give one of your fans
a heart attack,
you won't be able
to resuscitate him.
I need more space
in my matrix.
For what?
To expand
my musical subroutines,
so that I can sing
this composition.
Well, I'm surprised
you're asking me for help.
I recall your saying that
my appreciation for music
was limited to "a smattering
of Klingon drinking songs."
Please, B'Elanna.
I'm asking you
as a friend.
Everything depends
on this.
What's so important
about this composition?
Tincoo wrote it for me.
Your girlfriend?
I wouldn't
call her that.
Don't tell me you
two had a fight.
Let's just say,
she doesn't appreciate me quite
as much as I thought she did.
But that will all change.
Once I perform this,
she will see me for
the artist I truly am.
Look, Doc, I don't know
anything about this woman,
or why she doesn't
appreciate you,
and I may not be
an expert on music,
but I'm
a pretty good engineer.
I can expand your musical
subroutines all you like.
I can even reprogram you
to be a whistling teapot,
but, if I do that,
you won't be you anymore.
Tonight, I was planning
to perform a song
composed by one
of your own people.
When you consider she heard
music for the first time
only a few days ago,
it's an extraordinary
accomplishment.
But although it's
a very beautiful composition,
I'm afraid
it's beyond my abilities.
( murmuring )
So instead, I'm going to sing
an old Neapolitan ballad.
It's a song about lost love.
( singing in Italian)
( singing continues )
( moderate applause )
Thank you, Doctor.
That was fascinating.
It is because of
your inspiration that I can
now present to you
a new and exciting
musical program--
a singing
holographic matrix...
( audience murmuring )
designed specifically
to extend the range
of humanoid vocal capabilities,
singing
my own musical composition.
( singing sustained note )
( singing scales
in tenor and bass tones )
( singing notes in mixed
male and female voices)
( wild applause )
( singing continues )
( door chimes )
Come in.
Good morning, Captain.
What's this?
A formal request
to be reinstated.
So you've taken off your tails
and put them between your legs.
Yes, ma'am.
You offended a lot of people
who care about you.
I know.
I was a fool, I'm sorry,
and I'm willing to do whatever
I can to rectify the situation,
starting with the deletion
of all my musical subroutines.
Permission denied.
But, Captain...
No "buts", Doctor.
You're expected to
follow orders,
just like every other
flesh and blood
member of this crew.
Resume your normal activities--
all of them.
Yes, ma'am.
Dismissed.
( singing in Italian)
( singing stops abruptly )
Oh, Seven,
I didn't see you.
I suppose
you've come to gloat.
I have something
for you.
What is it?
Fan mail.
Delete it.
I don't want
to read another word.
Then I'll read
it for you.
Seven...
"Dear Doctor,
I regret that your
last performance
was not as successful
as you'd hoped.
There are still
those who appreciate
your unique talents
and admire you as an individual.
I'll always consider myself
your loyal fan."
Who's it from?
It's signed, "Seven of Nine,
Tertiary Adjunct
of Unimatrix 01."
♪ I've been working
on the railroad ♪
♪ All the livelong day ♪
♪ I've been working
on the railroad ♪
♪ Just to pass the time away ♪
♪ Can't you hear
the whistle blowing? ♪
♪ Rise up
so early in the morn... ♪