Who left their dirty plate
in the replicator? Tom?
It wasn't me.
It's a biohazard!
Take it easy!
We'll decontaminate you
when we get back home.
If I ever volunteer
for a two-week
away mission again,
would somebody please
confine me to Sick Bay?
Too much togetherness
for you, Harry?
Nothing personal, Commander.
To tell you
the truth,
I've enjoyed
our little junket together.
It's given the four of us
a chance to bond.
The bonding stopped
when the sonic shower
went off-line.
That's all part
of the experience,
the adventure.
Think of the great explorers
that came before us.
They survived
without creature comforts.
I wouldn't want to bunk
with them, either.
Now, there's a sight
for sore eyes.
CHAKOTAY:
Delta Flyer to Voyager.
We're on our approach.
JANEWAY:
We've kept a candle burning
in the window for you.
Forget the candles.
Break out the champagne!
JANEWAY:
I take it
the mission was a success.
15 planets scanned in 14 days.
We've got a cargo hold
overflowing with dilithium ore.
JANEWAY:
That's the kind of news
I like to hear.
The explorers
return.
Welcome home.
I should go away
more often.
I'm not going
anywhere for
a long, long time.
Homesick, Harry?
Well, let's just say
I'm looking forward
to a hot shower and
a comfortable bed.
Don't forget to stop
by Sick Bay for
your checkup.
Checkup? For what?
Away team protocol.
Crew members are required
to submit to a physical
if the mission lasts
more than two weeks.
Now...
who's first?
( sighs )
I'll let you know
in the morning, Doctor.
Why put off till tomorrow
what you can do today...
Commander?
Mr. Paris?
I've been working
on a little surprise for you.
Oh! Naughty or nice?
Close your eyes.
I like it already.
( chuckling )
Come on.
So, what do you think?
( laughs ):
A television set!
Circa 1956.
I replicated
the components,
but I assembled it myself.
( sighs )
This... is
the remote control.
You select
what you want to watch
by pressing this button.
PARIS:
A slight problem.
There were no remote
controls in the 1950s.
I took a little
poetic license.
( soft chuckle )
( music plays on TV )
Cartoon!
I found them
in the ship's database.
ANNOUNCER:
Vacuum action!
♪ Mop, mop ♪
♪ Don't stop... ♪
What's that?
Now, that is called a "jingle."
According to the research
I did, they inserted them
into the entertainment
programs.
I know, it's confusing,
but I kept them in
for authenticity.
I even replicated
popcorn.
Aw...
Mm!
Everything is perfect,
except for one
tiny detail.
What?
You forgot the beer.
I can fix that.
You didn't miss much
while you were away.
The Doctor
gave a lecture
on "Insects Indigenous
to the Delta Quadrant."
Uh-huh.
It was pretty
boring...
until Ensign Farley
started snoring,
and then no one could
keep a straight face.
Of course, the Doctor
wasn't at all amused.
PARIS:
Oh!
Hockey.
It was a shame
that we had to cut
the lecture short,
but the warp core
overloaded, and then
the Borg invaded,
and we were all
assimilated.
Mm-hmm.
You haven't heard
a single thing
I've said, have you?
Oh! Look at that!
Maybe this was
a bad idea.
It's Eliot Ness! Come on out!
We don't want any trouble!
( glass breaking )
WOMAN:
We're the Barkers!
You're never going to get us!
( gunfire )
We're under attack.
Stay down!
Keep moving!
( weapons fire )
Somebody cover me!
( gasps )
Need a medic over here!
Move it!
( weapons fire )
Stay low!
Aah!
Hold your fire!
I said
hold your fire!
I need a medic!
Keep moving!
( gasps )
TORRES:
Tom?
( groaning )
( weapons fire )
Tom?
Mm.
Must've been one
hell of a dream.
I was...
I was in the middle
of a battlefield.
I was grazed right...
right here.
( sighs )
They always said television
was a bad influence.
How about a
nice cartoon?
That should chase
away the nightmare.
No!
No, I think
I've had enough.
( voices yelling )
MALE:
Stay down!
Stay low!
( yelling continues )
( voices cease )
( labored breathing )
It sounds like you had
an anxiety attack.
I've never been
claustrophobic before.
There's a first time
for everything.
Do you know
what could've caused it?
Let's see...
you spend two weeks
on an away mission,
working 18-hour days.
Then, as soon as you
return to Voyager,
you become
"Ensign Eager,"
back on duty
and rarin' to go.
I had work to do.
There was a plasma
leak on Deck 5.
Plasma leak
or no plasma leak,
you're suffering
from exhaustion.
I'm recommending you take
the next two days off.
But I...
I can always
make it three.
You win.
Guess I am
pretty tired.
( kettle whistling )
Ah.
Welcome back.
( startled gasp )
Hello.
Did you have
a good trip?
Wonderful, thank you.
You look tired.
Oh, no. It's just
a little shuttle lag.
Don't you have
a geometry lesson?
You don't want to keep
your teacher waiting.
Seven of Nine assigned me
a special project.
I'm supposed to build
a tetragon,
but I have to use
everyday things.
I'm not allowed
to use a replicator.
I was thinking about using
some vegetables
from the Airponics Bay.
Carrots and celery?
Neelix?
Carrots and celery.
A good idea.
Will you help me?
Uh... I don't think
I'll have time today.
Tonight?
I don't think that I'll
have time then, either.
A lot of work to do!
Well, then, why
don't I help you?
What's cooking?
Ouch!
Let me see
your hand!
I'm okay.
Your hand!
We've got to get
you to Sick Bay.
I'm fine.
Sick Bay!
( laughter )
That's the best joke
I've ever heard.
Get down.
Stay behind me.
What?!
I said get down!
Go, go! Quickly!
Come on!
Help me with this!
Keep moving!
Try not to move.
Get away from me!
I can help you.
I don't... want your help!
MALE:
We need help over here!
Hold your fire.
I said hold your fire!
We're under attack, sir!
Saavdra-- where is he?
I think he's at base.
We were supposed to
evacuate the colony,
not destroy it!
That was before the Nakan
started shooting.
They're civilians!
Civilians
with particle weapons.
Tuvok to Commander Chakotay.
( gasping )
Commander, please respond.
Go ahead.
We have a security breach
in the Mess Hall.
I'm on my way.
Tell them to call off
the attack!
Put down your weapon, Neelix.
Let us help you.
Stay away!
I won't let you
hurt her!
Get back!
He appears to be
hallucinating.
Neelix! This is
Commander Chakotay!
Let Naomi go!
No one's going
to hurt her!
That's an order!
No!
Not until Saavdra's
called off his attack.
There's a back entrance
to the galley.
If you can distract
him, perhaps...
I want to try
something first.
Neelix!
Listen to me.
It's okay.
Saavdra ordered
a cease-fire.
The colony's secure.
The battle's over.
Why do I still
hear weapons fire?
It's just a few soldiers.
They're celebrating.
The battle's over.
Neelix, please.
I'll protect Naomi.
How do I know
you won't trick me?
Because I'm on your side.
I want to end this conflict
as much as you do.
Let her go.
It's safe now.
The killing's over.
I gave him
a mild sedative.
Any idea what caused
the delusions?
His norepinephrine levels are
three times what they should be.
Neurochemically speaking,
he's suffering from a form
of post-traumatic
stress syndrome.
I dreamed I was fighting
in an alien war.
The same war Neelix
seemed to be reliving.
Harry Kim was in earlier.
He had an anxiety attack.
I haven't spoken
with Mr. Paris yet.
Three members
of the same away team.
Did you run into any kind
of trouble while you were gone?
None. The mission
was by the book.
Your engramatic activities
contradict that, Commander.
These are real memories,
not mere dreams
or hallucinations.
Maybe you were abducted...
manipulated
into fighting.
Our memories have been
tampered with before.
We're going to retrace
your mission.
Start reviewing
the Delta Flyer
sensor logs.
See if you come up
with anything unusual.
How long before Neelix
is back on his feet?
I can wake him now
if you'd like.
Do it.
Each of you seems to hold
a piece of the puzzle.
Let's see if we can start
putting them together.
I don't remember much,
just bits and pieces.
I dreamt I was on a planet
in the middle of a battle.
I have no idea
how I got there.
I can't remember.
When I was in
the Jefferies tube, I heard
weapons fire, screams.
People were screaming.
I got so frightened.
Of what?
I... I don't know.
I remember
getting shot.
There's no evidence
of a wound.
If our memories were wiped,
our physical injuries
could have been masked as well.
Do any of you recall
who you were fighting?
It was dark.
I couldn't see them very well.
They were
firing at us.
The Naka... Na... Nakana...
Nakan.
They were called
the Nakan.
Right. Right.
They... they lived
in a remote colony.
We were trying
to evacuate them.
But they were fighting us.
Why couldn't they just
do what they were told?
We had no right to be there!
It was for
their own good.
Gentlemen,
stay focused.
You said you were
trying to evacuate
their colony. Why?
Those were our orders.
Who gave them?
Saavdra.
Commander Saavdra.
He was in charge of our unit.
We were part of an attack force.
You were coerced?
No!
No, I volunteered.
We all did.
I find that difficult
to believe.
You were obviously
manipulated somehow.
No! No, no, no, no,
I remember now.
We held a, uh, a briefing
to plan the evacuation.
You were there, Commander.
Mr. Paris!
It was a command post.
That's right.
It was night, 0200 hours.
We'd been awake for days.
We were exhausted.
What do our spotters report?
The Nakan are unarmed.
They won't put up a fight.
Once we've disabled
their shield generators,
we'll deploy Units 5 and 6.
They may be unarmed, but they
won't be happy to see us.
Don't provoke them.
I want to come out of this
with zero casualties
on both sides.
Understood.
The perimeter is the weakest
in Sector 14.
The terrain's very flat.
It's an ideal landing spot
for transports.
Once we've secured
the village,
take the
colonists there.
Get them aboard.
Do your best to
reassure them.
Make them understand that this
is a temporary relocation,
that they're going
to be back there
within a few weeks.
Understood.
ALL: Yes, sir!
Aye, aye, sir.
Problem?
Just one.
This unit could
use a little sleep.
I suggest we wait
until daybreak.
I promised Command
we'd have this colony
secured today.
It can wait a few hours.
I'm sorry.
But when this mission's over,
how does a week
on Toranius Prime sound?
Never been there.
Compared to this place,
it's paradise.
The mission proceeded
as planned.
We disabled their
shield generators
and entered the colony.
We were rounding up the Nakan.
To be honest, I expected them to
give us a little more trouble.
But then we came
to the last enclosure.
Do you remember
the last enclosure?
It was empty.
Where were they?
They were supposed
to be there.
24 colonists
unaccounted for.
We thought the spotters
had made a mistake.
We should've known
something was wrong.
We should've
gotten out then.
This way.
Stay in line.
Keep moving.
Evacuation detail to base.
We're ready
for transport.
MAN:
Transports on approach.
Keep moving.
I have to find
my husband.
Don't worry.
He'll be on one
of the transports.
Which one?
I, I don't know,
but we'll find him.
( weapons fire )
Everybody down!
Base, we're under attack.
Repeat, we're
under attack.
Those missing colonists,
they were armed.
They fired the first shots.
It wasn't our fault.
You can't be sure of that.
It could've been
one of our own people.
Fatigue, a phaser
malfunction--
you just don't know!
Either way, it doesn't
justify what we did.
What did you do?
What happened
down there?
Keep moving.
Stay together!
( colonists screaming )
Hold your fire!
Stay down!
( colonists clamoring )
Stay together!
Stop running! Stop!
Get down!
Get down! Get down!
Stop running!
I said stop!
We didn't have any other choice.
Like hell, we didn't.
They were
wiping us out!
That didn't give us
the right to murder civilians.
I tried to protect
the children,
but I couldn't stop them
from running away.
I ran, too.
Sounds of phaser fire,
people shouting...
I had to get out of there.
( panting and grunting )
( gasps )
( woman gasps )
FEMALE:
Please, please, don't hurt us!
Move out
where I can see you!
Move!
Please. Please,
he's no threat to you.
Tell me how I can
get out of these tunnels,
and I'll leave you alone.
Tell me!
Oh!
Go back the way you came.
At the second fork,
take the tunnel to your left,
follow it
to the end.
It will lead you
to the river.
( weapons fire and screaming)
He was going to kill me.
Easy, Harry.
They wouldn't listen!
Why?
Why wouldn't
they listen?
We killed 82 civilians
that night.
No one was left alive.
Captain's Log, supplemental.
We've entered the system
where the away team
conducted its recent survey,
hoping to find
an explanation
for their memories
of the Nakan massacre.
( door chimes )
Yeah.
Yeah!
Missed you at breakfast.
I wasn't hungry.
Sleep a little?
Five, ( sighs )
six minutes.
I found another episode
of The Untouchables.
Eliot Ness captures
someone named Al Cay-pone.
"Capone."
Maybe later.
Well, you've got
to eat something.
Pizza?
Look, I appreciate what
you're trying to do,
but I'd rather
just be alone.
Tom...
No!
I don't want to be...
comforted right now.
I know the last few days
have been difficult.
Oh. "Difficult."
"Difficult" doesn't
quite cover it.
I helped murder
82 innocent people.
You don't know that.
I know what I remember.
The Doctor says
your memories could
have been altered.
I was there!
When I close my eyes,
I can see the bodies.
I-I can hear
the weapons fire!
I can feel
where I was shot!
Then why isn't there
evidence of a war...?
I don't know!
All I'm asking
is that you consider
the possibility that
this didn't happen.
We'll keep
investigating.
There are sensor readings
on the Delta Flyer
that we haven't
even analyzed yet.
I-I can't concentrate
on sensor readings right now.
Try.
I can't! Stop pushing me!
I don't want your help!
I'm sorry.
You know where to find me.
This was your first
stop on the away mission,
a Class-M planet with
one natural satellite.
Did you send anyone
to the surface?
No, we only scanned
for dilithium deposits.
We were in orbit
for less than an hour.
Next.
You came into contact
with this vessel
en route to your second
destination.
CHAKOTAY:
Captain Bathar of Hodos.
Photogenic.
He's a merchant.
Claimed to have a formula
that stops the aging process.
Oh, you didn't happen
to buy any, did you?
It was only
a tripolymer enzyme.
Makes great
shoe polish, though.
Moving on.
Your second stop.
( screams )
Tarakis.
( gasps )
The planet, it's called Tarakis.
I've been here.
( weapons fire )
What the hell
are you doing?!
Stand aside.
They're already dead!
They were never here.
We disabled their
shield generators,
entered the colony
and they were gone.
No one's going
to believe that.
They will if we all
keep to the same story.
I won't lie about
what happened here.
Then you say nothing.
We murdered these people!
In self-defense!
If that were true,
you wouldn't be
vaporizing the evidence!
You don't have
to listen to him.
We've got to let people know.
We panicked!
They'll understand!
No, they won't!
Move away.
I said move away!
( weapon fires )
( gasps )
How long have
I been here?
Three hours.
You started hallucinating
in Astrometrics.
I'm afraid
I had to sedate you.
I was there.
I was at
the colony...
with Saavdra.
You're not the only one.
39 crew members
have begun to experience
the same memories.
TUVOK:
It appears
that the entire crew
has been affected.
( panting )
DOCTOR:
Their symptoms
are identical--
increased engramatic
activity, nightmares.
I can imagine
the away team
being pulled
into an alien conflict.
But these people weren't
anywhere near this system.
We've analyzed
Voyager's
sensor records.
If we did participate
in a war,
all evidence of it
has been erased.
The dream was so vivid--
as real as anything
I've experienced.
But I refuse to believe
that we could...
Real or not,
the memories
are having a deleterious effect
on the crew.
The syndrome began to spread
once we entered this system.
I suggest we
reverse course,
before it
gets worse.
No. If this massacre really
happened, someone is to blame.
I want to be certain
that it wasn't us.
With all due respect,
your judgment
may be clouded by
feelings of guilt
about an incident
that never occurred.
The danger
to our crew
here and now,
is indisputable.
I've seen you
looking better, Ensign.
Yes, ma'am.
I've felt better myself,
but we're going
to get through this.
The massacre took
place on Tarakis.
Go to Red Alert
and set a course.
Aye, Captain.
A neural suppressant.
It'll help keep
the memories from resurfacing.
Your favorites--
Talaxian stew
and terra nut soufflé.
The soufflé
has collapsed slightly,
but its nutritional content
is intact.
Thank you.
It looks delicious.
When Naomi Wildman is sad,
she consumes desserts.
She claims it improves
her emotional state.
Perhaps you should try it.
Naomi must be terrified of me...
after what happened
in the galley.
She's concerned about you.
She told me she wants
to visit you.
No, not like this.
I might do something
to scare her again.
I'll give her your regards.
Seven...
When you were a Borg,
you were involved in some...
unpleasant activities.
I helped to assimilate millions.
I don't mean to be insensitive,
but... do you ever feel shame
about what you did?
Frequently.
How do you manage
to keep going,
knowing that you've done
such horrible things?
I have no choice.
Guilt is irrelevant?
On the contrary,
my feelings of remorse
help me remember what I did
and prevent me from taking
similar actions in the future.
Guilt can be a difficult
but useful emotion.
It's certainly difficult.
Is that chocolate mixed in there
with the terra nuts?
I altered the
recipe slightly.
I hope you
don't object.
Not at all.
Tarakis, dead ahead.
Shields.
Stand by weapons.
On screen.
Scan for vessels.
There are none.
Take us into orbit.
Ma'am?
Do it, Mr. Paris.
Life signs?
The planet appears
to be uninhabited.
Looks the same as it did
a few days ago,
when we scanned
for dilithium deposits.
Signs of weapons fire
or phaser residue?
Negative.
Run a full
spectral scan.
Look for anything unusual.
Nothing on geometric sensors.
Hold on. I'm picking up
a power signature.
Source?
I can't tell.
The signal's erratic,
but it's coming
from the northernmost continent,
coordinates 172 mark 5.
Phasers.
( birds chirping )
Call it an educated guess,
but I don't think this
looks like a war zone.
There's something familiar
about it though.
I recognize those mountains.
Those trees weren't here.
Search the area.
( bird cawing )
Ensign?
The tunnel.
It's nearby.
The one where I, uh...
How'd you get into it?
There was a rock formation.
It hid the opening.
A faint energy signature.
This way.
Over here.
( sighs )
There's your
physical evidence.
I suggest we proceed
with caution.
Stand guard.
( tricorder beeping
insistently )
( panting )
( panicky breathing )
I... I... I can't.
Remain calm.
Slow, deep breaths.
( breathing deeply )
They were over there.
( tricorder beeping )
I found the remains
of two humanoids,
but you were not responsible
for their deaths.
They died
over 300 years ago.
( sighs )
( tricorder beeping )
( beeping insistently )
I think we found our war.
The structure contains
a synaptic transmitter.
I believe
it was designed
to send neurogenic pulses
throughout this system.
So anyone passing through
would experience
the Nakan massacre...
like we did.
SEVEN: Precisely.
Try running those symbols
inscribed on the base
through the translation matrix.
"Words alone cannot
convey the suffering.
Words alone cannot prevent
what happened here
from happening again.
Beyond words lies experience.
Beyond experience lies truth.
Make this truth
your own."
It's a memorial.
We weren't victims
of a conspiracy.
We were witnesses to a massacre.
More than witnesses.
By being forced
to relive those events,
half the crew's
been traumatized.
Maybe that was the point.
I certainly won't forget
what happened here.
Anything in that database
that might tell us who built
this thing?
No. The technology
has been neglected
for more than two centuries.
Its power cells
are deteriorating.
That could explain
why our memories
were so fragmented.
It was probably designed
to transmit the experience
in sequence.
Fascinating.
Now let's try to shut it down
so nobody else
has to go through this.
Kathryn?
Yes, of course.
Even if we do shut down
the transmitter,
I'm afraid your memories
of the massacre are permanent.
But we'll prevent this
from happening to
other passing ships.
If we do that,
all record
of what happened here
would be lost.
The monument
will still be here.
But that doesn't really
tell the story.
Someone put a lot
of time and care into
building that transmitter.
We can't just deactivate it.
We don't have the right.
Did they have the right
to force us to relive all that?
They wanted others to know
what it was like,
in the hopes
that nothing like it
would happen again.
Why should anyone have to
experience an atrocity
they didn't commit?
Because that's how you learn
not to make the same mistake.
If we destroy the evidence,
we're no better than Saavdra.
Maybe he had a point.
It wasn't our fault.
Given the danger involved,
it's only logical...
This isn't about logic!
It's about remembering!
Some things
are best forgotten.
Not this.
I stood by once before
and did nothing.
Not again.
Captain?
I watched while Saavdra
vaporized the bodies.
No offense, but those were
other people's memories.
The Obelisk at Khitomer,
the fields at Gettysburg,
those were other people's
memories, too,
but we don't
honor them any less.
The 82 colonists
who died here...
they deserve their memorial.
Captain...
We're not going to shut down
the transmitter. Is that clear?
Is that clear?
Are you suggesting
we leave it intact?
I'm suggesting
that we repair it.
Recharge the power cells.
I want that monument
to function properly
for another 300 years.
We'll place
a warning buoy in orbit.
Anyone who enters this system
will know what to expect.
Dismissed.
We're ready, Captain.
I know this was hardest
on the four of you,
but if you hadn't
stopped at this planet,
all the people who died here
would have been forgotten.
And if they could,
I know they'd thank you.
Janeway to Voyager.
Stand by to initiate
power transfer.
Five to beam up.
( monument powering up )