( loud chatter )
( loud, percussive music plays)
( crowd shouting )
( buzzer sounds )
( shouting )
( both grunting )
( buzzer sounds )
( crowd chanting ):
Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Tsunkat! Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Captain's Log,
Stardate 53447.2.
The crew's enjoying
a much needed shore leave
on the Norcadian
homeworld.
While I visit Pendari,
a planet in the
neighboring system,
I'm leaving
Commander Chakotay
in charge of Voyager.
You may want to run a diagnostic
on the shield generators.
It's way overdue.
Consider it done.
And don't forget to keep tabs
on Neelix's little project
in the Mess Hall.
He's still trying
to enhance
the plasma burners
in his stove?
With some of Seven's
Borg technology.
I don't want him accidentally
turning the galley into
an assimilation chamber.
I'll assign
a security detail
to keep tabs on him--
unless you think
we need to take more
drastic measures.
And most important,
be sure to tell your Captain
when she's being overprotective.
I'll do that.
Thanks again
for minding the store.
Even the Captain deserves
a vacation once in a while.
And her First Officer?
He's looking forward
to putting his feet up
on your desk.
Chakotay.
Fun last night, wasn't it?
There's another match
scheduled at 1500.
I've got a systems diagnostic.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but you're in command until
the Captain gets back.
What's your point?
Delegate.
I happen to know that
Harry's free this afternoon.
Lieutenant, you're
not suggesting
I abuse my power.
( chuckling )
Tell me that's
not lunch.
It's leola ointment
for my skin.
What happened?
I was so excited to visit
one of those beautiful
Norcadian beaches, uh,
that I forgot to take
my dermaline hypospray.
I fell asleep...
under two suns.
Ouch.
( chuckling weakly )
A little more color
than I was hoping for,
but it'll be a beautiful amber
before you know it.
How's your shore leave been?
Well, we've spent the last few
days at the Tsunkatse matches.
Tsunkatse.
I heard some crewmen talking
about that during breakfast.
It's exciting--
a real test of
strength and agility.
You should come to the match
with us this afternoon.
From what I've heard,
Tsunkatse is crude
and pointless.
Well, I guess we won't be
saving you a seat.
What about
you, Tuvok?
You appreciate
the martial arts.
I have other plans.
There's a micronebula
approximately 1.6
light-years from here
on the verge of collapse.
SEVEN:
We'd like to take
a shuttle to study it.
Ah. An away mission
during shore leave?
Commander Tuvok and I don't
require recreational activities.
The Borg wouldn't know fun
if they assimilated
an amusement park.
It's your shore leave,
but try to enjoy yourselves.
That's an order.
Here's the navigational
data you asked for.
Thank you.
How long are you
planning on being gone?
Approximately 48 hours.
( chuckles ):
Just like B'Elanna.
Clarify.
Well, she
overpacks, too.
I haven't overpacked.
I simply wish to be prepared
for any contingency.
And what contingency
is this for?
That's an iso-modulator,
enhanced to correct
hull ablation
in the event
we encounter
a meteoroid stream.
Well, couldn't you just
replicate an iso-modulator?
I prefer this one.
Oh, I get it.
You like to have your
own things with you.
B'Elanna's
the same way.
You know, she'd never admit it,
but she still takes
a stuffed animal with her
whenever she's
going to be away
for more than a day.
Toby the targ.
Can Toby the targ
correct hull ablation?
Your comparison is flawed.
Just the person
I was looking for.
You require my assistance?
Your company.
I was wondering
if you'd care to
join me on a tour
of Norcadia's
cultural hot spots.
I hear their museums
are among the finest
in this sector.
I'm busy.
With what?
Commander Tuvok and I
are leaving
to study a collapsing
micronebula.
During shore leave?
I thought we'd
discussed this.
Shore leave is
a perfect opportunity
for you to spend time
with other members
of the crew
to develop
your social skills.
Then I suppose I'll have
to develop them with
Commander Tuvok.
Vulcans aren't exactly known
for their winning personalities.
You'd prefer I spent my time
with more sociable individuals,
such as yourself?
You could do worse.
In that case, perhaps
you'd care to join us.
To study the
micronebula?
You can assist us
with our analysis
of veridium-oxide particulates.
On second thought,
you and Tuvok
have a good time.
I'll give the Commander
your regrets.
Uh, do that.
And if the nebula
isn't as riveting
as you'd hoped,
try to remember Lesson 36--
"Pleasant Parlor Games
to Pass the Time."
( quietly ):
You'll need it.
Two hours, 37 minutes,
13 seconds.
That's how long
we've gone without
verbal communication.
Why is that remarkable?
The Doctor encourages me
to engage in conversation
during awkward silences.
Did you find
the silence awkward?
No.
Nor did I.
( console beeping )
There's a vessel approaching
on an intercept course.
The hull configuration
is unfamiliar.
Distance?
Approximately
300,000 kilometers.
Hail them.
No response.
Tuvok to Voyager.
The vessel is
emitting some kind
of dampening field.
We've lost engines,
weapons, shields.
( whoosh of active transport)
It's an explosive device
of some sort.
Transporters are down.
I can't beam it off.
I'll try to disarm it.
Borg-enhanced physiology.
You should have
superior strength, agility,
stamina,
visual acuity.
Welcome to Tsunkatse.
Since the game's inception,
our audience has never had
the pleasure
of seeing a
drone compete.
You are going to be
a very popular attraction.
Where is Commander Tuvok?
MALE:
Your comrade
from the shuttle?
I'm afraid
he was injured
in the explosion.
I wish to see him now.
Certainly.
You'll learn nothing
is more important to me
than the comfort and happiness
of my fighters.
Yes, Penk's generosity
is... legendary.
( laughing )
Quiet!
He's envious because I've found
a new favorite.
I have no intention
of participating in your game.
Aggressive. I like that.
( hatch opens )
( panting )
He requires
medical attention.
That can be arranged.
Then arrange it.
You haven't won
a single bout
and already you're
making demands
like a champion.
Will you treat him or not?
Will you fight?
TUVOK:
Do not comply.
My condition is not severe.
Spoken like
a true competitor,
willing to ignore
his injuries
for the sake
of the contest.
Schedule a
bout for him.
A Red Match against
the Pensarkan.
HUNTER:
A Red Match
does not end until one
of the competitors is killed.
Your friend would not survive.
But you might.
HUNTER:
Give her a Blue Match, Penk.
You wouldn't want to lose
your new favorite
her first time in the pit.
Yes. We should
start you off slowly.
( moaning )
Treat him...
and I will comply.
What about the seventh match?
I'm picking the Vensiddian.
He lost
his last two times out.
But he's undefeated
against left-handed fighters.
You should
trust him, Harry.
Chakotay knows a thing or two
about southpaws.
He was 23 and 0
as a light heavyweight.
23 and one,
actually...
a Nausicaan with
a mean right hook.
You think that's bad?
Try taking a parrises
mallet to the ribs.
I didn't know you played.
Three-time Academy champion.
Now, that's a tough sport.
I boxed a few parrises players
in my day.
And?
Let's just say
they went back
to playing parrises
squares after that.
( all laugh )
Oh, is that a challenge,
Commander?
( chuckles ):
I wouldn't want
to put my Ops Officer out
of commission, now, would I?
Oh... I can take a punch.
Careful, Harry.
Legend has it that
the "Tattooed Terror"
has put more men in Sick Bay
than the Ankaran flu.
Yeah, you wouldn't want
to bruise your clarinet fingers.
( laughter )
Hey, you want
to go a few rounds,
or all you all talk?
Any time, any place.
Oh, you punch
like a Ferengi.
( laughter )
I don't care
what Harry says.
The Pensarkan-Bendali match
is too close to call.
I'll let you know
how it turns out.
Excuse me?
I rearranged the duty
schedules this morning.
You've got the Bridge
starting at 1400 hours.
You're sticking me
with that shift
so that you can go to the fight.
I'm delegating.
Oh, me and my big mouth.
I thought you'd be pleased
that I took your advice.
Words fail me.
Now, remind me.
The reason that you have
to see that fight
is because...?
I'm an anthropologist.
What does that have
to do with Tsunkatse?
It's a cultural phenomenon.
You're having
an allergic reaction
to your
leola ointment.
I hope you've
learned your lesson.
Talaxian homeopathy
is no substitute
for medical science.
This should help with the
swelling and discoloration.
Ow.
But you'll have
to stay out of the sun.
But what about the rest
of my shore leave?
I suggest you limit it
to indoor activities.
Commander Chakotay
and B'Elanna invited me
to the Tsunkatse matches.
I guess I'll go.
I'm disappointed in
you, Mr. Neelix.
Cheering for one individual
to inflict
serious injury on another
hardly seems like
an activity you'd enjoy.
Well, Commander Chakotay says
that it's a wonderful
demonstration of
athletic prowess.
You seem to be forgetting
that Commander Chakotay
is an aficionado of boxing,
arguably the most barbaric sport
in Earth's history.
Surely you can find some way
to occupy your free time
that doesn't involve
alien fisticuffs.
Do you have any suggestions?
As a matter of fact,
I was planning a visit
to the Norcadian
Museum of Entomology
this afternoon.
There's a fascinating
exhibit of beetle larvae
from the equatorial
subcontinent.
You're welcome
to join me.
Hmm, alien bugs
or alien fisticuffs.
Oh, that's a tough one.
Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Tsunkat! Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
( whooping )
You were right, Commander.
This is exciting.
Two opponents alone in the pit
with only their strength
and agility
to protect them.
I'm glad
you're enjoying yourself.
I still don't understand
the rules.
It's simple.
A Tsunkatse fighter
wears a polaron disruptor
on both hands and feet.
Each disruptor delivers
a bioplasmic charge
when it comes in contact
with one of the opponent's
target sensors.
So there is strategy involved.
A fighter has to attack
his rival's sensors
without exposing his own.
Are you two going to talk
or you here to watch?
( buzzer sounds )
( crowd cheering wildly )
He looks like he could
pick up a shuttlecraft.
He's a Pendari.
They're known for their
superior strength.
And their bad temper.
I hear they have a tendency
to throw their opponents
into the stands.
Be ready to duck.
( chuckles )
( crowd jeering )
Seven?
Seven!
You're no bigger than
a Tarkanian field mouse.
Penk's insulting me by putting
you in the pit to face me.
I must warn you,
I possess superior strength.
I'm trembling.
( laughter )
Seven!
NEELIX:
I assure you,
resistance is futile.
So is all your talk.
Seven!
It's no use.
She can't hear us.
Chakotay to Voyager.
Come in.
Calling to give me
a blow-by-blow description
of the match, Commander?
Seven of Nine is in the pit.
What?
No time to explain.
Beam her out of there!
I have no desire to
inflict further damage.
I'm afraid I can't
say the same.
I'm locked onto
the coordinates of the pit.
Seven's not there.
I'm looking right at her!
Not according to these sensors.
Maybe their life signs
are masked.
Try recalibrating
the bio-scanners.
Acknowledged.
TORRES:
There's nothing to lock on to.
The only readings I'm picking up
are photonic.
Holograms?
They're transmitting
the fight
from another location.
( grunting )
( beeping )
Transmission to one of
the arenas on Norcadia Prime
is being disrupted.
Compensate.
( crowd shouting )
CROWD:
Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Tsunkat! Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Voyager, four to beam up.
CHAKOTAY:
We've scanned
the Norcadian surface, Captain.
There's no sign of them.
Any luck tracing
the transmission?
We're trying, but it's not easy.
There are transmissions
being sent to every
planet in the sector.
I guess you aren't the only ones
who enjoy this sport.
It could take days
before we can figure out
where Seven and Tuvok
are being held.
What about diplomatic channels?
Neelix is meeting
with a group of
Norcadian officials.
Well, let's hope he gets
their cooperation.
CHAKOTAY:
When can we
expect you back?
I'm at the outer rim
of the Pendari system.
At best, I'm 48 hours away.
Sorry to cut your
vacation short.
That's okay, Commander.
Keep me informed.
Janeway out.
( gasps )
Stay away from me.
It's a dermal regenerator.
The Pendari you
fought injured you.
Now, keep still.
It's almost out
of power.
I'd prefer that you use it
to treat Commander Tuvok.
I already have.
He's sleeping.
Why are you helping us?
I recognize fellow hunters
when I see them.
I'm no hunter.
I saw your match today.
Your skills are impressive.
The Pendari would disagree.
You almost defeated him,
but at the last moment,
you hesitated.
You... questioned
your desire
to destroy your prey.
I have no such desire.
Don't you?
I thought I saw it in your eyes.
With the
proper training,
you could become a champion.
Until our ship comes
to rescue us,
my only goal is to survive.
Do you know the difference
between a survivor
and a champion here?
There isn't one.
( hatch opens,
footsteps approach )
I wanted to be the first
to congratulate you.
I lost.
Exactly.
There's a great deal
of hostility toward the Borg
in this sector.
Whenever the Pendari landed
a blow, our audience grew.
We're getting
tens of thousands of requests
to see you fight again.
HUNTER:
She needs time
to recuperate--
to prepare for her next bout.
I agree.
There's a Red Match
scheduled for the day
after tomorrow.
The Pendari
was supposed to compete,
but I've entered
you in his place.
( chuckling )
If three billion people paid
to see you hurt,
imagine how many will pay
to see you die.
Survival may be more difficult
than I imagined.
You will win the match.
What makes you say that?
I know your opponent;
I know his weaknesses.
I can train you to defeat him.
I told you, I will not kill
anyone in that arena.
Consider the alternative.
Teach me.
You're letting
your elbow fall,
exposing your target.
You're mistaken.
My arm is positioned properly.
"When executing
the Tanyk Defense,
the blocking elbow must remain
parallel
to the median sensor."
Ah, the Book of Tsunkatse.
Commander Tuvok borrowed it
from one of the other fighters.
It is obvious
you've studied it well.
I'm attempting to perfect
a defense against...
( grunts )
That was not one of
the 33 sanctioned
maneuvers.
There must be 34.
I was unprepared
for your attack.
Is that what you're going to say
to your opponent?
Stop thinking like a drone.
Sanctioned maneuvers,
perfecting
defenses.
You cannot assimilate Tsunkatse
from a book.
You must live it, feel it.
In here.
Your movements
must become instinct.
An attack could come at any time
from any direction.
You must learn to improvise.
Like this?
( yells in pain )
I've observed you often favor
your left side.
Very perceptive.
It's a wound I sustained
in one of my first matches.
After 19 years,
it still hasn't healed properly.
You've been here a long time.
I was taken during
my son's first hunt.
He was so proud
to be with his father.
Watching every
movement I made,
imitating
my gestures.
But instead of bringing
home his first trophy,
he saw his father become
someone else's prey.
Do you know
what happened to him?
I never saw him again.
All Penk would say
was that the boy was
too small for competition.
Perhaps he managed
to return home.
( grunts )
You let down your defenses.
Why?
I was...
What?
Feeling sorry for me?
My tragic past?
Yes.
You must never sympathize
with your prey.
Unless you accept that,
you will die.
We'll continue.
How did it go?
Oh, the Norcadians
were shocked to learn
that off-worlders might be
participating against
their will.
Uh, the Ambassador
promised to begin
an immediate
investigation.
You don't sound
too convinced.
I'm not.
I spoke to one
of the Pendari delegates.
According to him,
a huge percentage
of the planet's revenue
is derived from Tsunkatse.
Nobody wants to do anything
that might interfere
with the game.
So they turn
a blind eye to the
recruitment tactics.
We're not going
to get any help through
official channels.
It's hard to believe
a-a-a civilization
whose favorite pastime
is cheering
while innocent people
fight each other.
If Seven and Tuvok
hadn't been abducted,
we might still
be cheering, too.
What have you got?
Well, one of the reasons
we were having trouble
isolating the source
of the transmissions
was because they never
seem to be coming
from the same
place twice.
At first, we thought
the matches
were being held
in various locations.
But when we
connected the dots,
we realized the pattern
conformed to a flight path.
One that spanned
the entire sector.
They're transmitting
the fights from a ship.
Like a traveling carnival.
Oh, this is
no carnival.
Five million
metric tons,
reinforced hull plating
protected
by covariant shielding,
neutronic weaponry.
It's way out
of our weight class.
The bigger they come,
Lieutenant.
Transmit these coordinates
to the Captain.
Tell her
we could use a hand.
Excellent.
When your opponent
enters the arena,
what do you see?
My prey.
And what do you do
to your prey?
Hunt it down
and kill it.
Go rest before
your match.
Thank you.
Thank me...
by winning.
Penk's guards are making
their inspection rounds.
Progress?
Both the dampening field
and the shielding
of this vessel
are tetryon-based.
But without access to
the control interface,
I can't disable either.
Your training?
Complete.
Are you adequately
prepared?
The Hirogen
is an efficient instructor.
He believes I'll win.
That troubles you.
The idea
of killing someone
for the entertainment
of others is detestable.
Is the idea
of losing your own life
for the entertainment of others
more palatable?
As a drone,
you took many lives.
I was acting as part
of the collective.
You're worried
you won't have the strength
to accomplish the task
on your own.
I'm worried that I will.
It's time.
Do whatever it takes
to survive.
( crowd shouting,
loud music playing )
( loud chatter )
( crowd jeering )
( booing continues )
( crowd cheering )
You knew.
Yes.
( buzzer sounds )
Training me was
a deception.
You wished to familiarize
yourself with my weaknesses.
I was helping you
to overcome them.
Why?
19 years is a long time.
I've grown tired.
You wish to be killed
in the arena.
I want a death my son
would be proud of.
I won't be the one
to provide it.
Then I'll be forced
to kill you.
Ya!
( loud cheering )
Approaching the vessel.
Take us out of warp.
Raise shields
and charge weapons.
Any sign of Tuvok and Seven?
Our sensors can't penetrate
their shields.
Hail them.
This is not a convenient time.
I'm Commander Chakotay of
the Starship Voyager.
You're holding
two of my people.
You'll have to be more specific.
Commander Tuvok
and Seven of Nine.
Return them, now.
The Borg drone and her friend.
I'm afraid
she's occupied at the moment.
You have 30 seconds
before I open fire.
A fighter.
I respect that,
but you're no match for me.
We can still find
another way out of this.
There is no other way.
You're still
dropping your elbow.
Make a choice,
hunter or prey?
( pained grunt )
Hunter or prey?
Direct hit to their
aft shield generators.
Still no sign of Seven,
but I've got a lock
on Tuvok.
Beam him to Sick Bay.
Keep targeting
those generators.
Transport complete.
Bridge to Tuvok.
Go ahead, Commander.
Do you know Seven's status?
She's being forced to fight...
to the death.
I believe
they're on the uppermost deck.
That section's protected
by multiphasic force fields.
I can't penetrate them.
Shields down to 40 percent.
32 percent.
You're getting weak.
I should have found
worthier prey.
You're imperfect.
Is that the best you can do?
Shields are down.
Evasive maneuvers.
Harry?
Still can't get a lock.
Should I get us out of here
before they knock out
our propulsion?
Not yet.
If we can't beam her out,
maybe we can shut down
the transmission.
If nobody's watching,
then why continue the fight?
Start targeting
their signal generators.
Hull breach on Deck 11.
Seal it.
Tsunkat! Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
We've lost weapons.
Another vessel is approaching.
Great. Now they're
bringing in reinforcements.
PARIS:
No, this one's
on our side.
It's the Delta Flyer.
CHAKOTAY:
Good to see you, Captain.
Nothing like getting back
to work after a long vacation.
We need you to target
their signal generators.
Understood.
( jeering and booing )
( console beeping )
We've lost more
than half our audience.
Reroute power
to Transmitters 5 and 6.
They've reduced power
to their force fields.
I've got two life
signs in there--
Seven and a Hirogen--
but I can't get
an individual lock.
Transport them both
if you have to.
Tom.
Aye, sir.
Tsunkat! Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
Tsunkat! Tsunkat!
( gasping weakly )
Never... let your prey suffer.
Kill it.
Seven, stand away.
It's all right.
This fight is over.
Captain's Log,
Stardate 53529.4.
We've resumed course
for the Alpha Quadrant
and initiated repairs.
I can't say I'm sorry
to see this shore leave
come to an end.
CHAKOTAY:
We've located
an Hirogen hunting party
three light-years away.
They've agreed
to rendezvous with us.
I'm grateful.
Would you excuse us?
Very well,
but if you should
need anything--
an analgesic,
a phaser rifle...
...don't hesitate
to ask.
I apologize for the Doctor.
He's very
protective of me.
He doesn't realize how
well you defend yourself.
A trophy.
What will you do now,
search for new prey?
No, this time I will be
searching for my son.
If he is as clever
as his father,
he may be difficult to locate.
I've been wondering.
Would you have killed me?
I don't know.
Ah...
Fortunately, you were right.
There was another way out.
I thought you might
require assistance.
Thank you.
I realize we share an
affinity for silences,
but in this instance...
I feel compelled
to speak.
If you hadn't offered
to take my place in the arena,
it's likely I would have
been killed.
I made the logical choice,
as you would have.
Still, I owe you
a debt of gratitude.
Assisting me
with these recalibrations
will be sufficient, thanks.
Have you
fully recovered?
I'm experiencing
minor pain
beneath my
occipital implant,
but the Doctor believes
it is temporary.
I wasn't referring to
your physical condition.
When the Hirogen referred
to me as weak,
he was correct.
But you overpowered him.
Because I
lost control.
Given the circumstances,
your behavior
was understandable.
I've spent the last three years
struggling to regain
my humanity.
I'm afraid I may have
lost it again in that arena.
You're experiencing
difficult emotions.
Guilt...
shame...
remorse.
Then you haven't lost
your humanity.
You have reaffirmed it.